.ragluv dna enecsbo ylpeed tlef os gniod fo thguoht eht
.daets rieht ni nworg dah stnalp tresed
.htaerb peed rehtona koot senemoelK
.seye s’rehto hcae otni ylgnignol gnirats doots yeht ,rehtona eno dnuora smra riehT
.detseggus selcohtagA ”.ereht peels nac ew kniht I ,denodnaba skool tI .mraf tahT“
.ylmrif dias erugif ehT
.thgirpu deyats tub ,dereggats tsaeb ehT
”?egassem eht wonk uoy oD“
.yletelpmoc ffo tnemrag s’esuom eht fo tfel saw tahw pir ot gnideecorp
.selcohtagA ot dna
ylno dah selcohtagA ,dekaN
seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
- .nolybaB fo snedraG gnignaH eht hcaer dluow yeht yad sihT
”.doof on ,retaw on evah ew tuB“
.derepsihw senemoelK
.yrarbil ymedaca eht morf llorcs a elots uoY“
.deilper selcohtagA
ekat …tsuj t’nac uoY
ssenredliw eht otni aiculeS fo modgnik eht delf
,s’tar eht revo sdnah sih decalp tar ehT
”.namdam a fo sgnilbmar eht tsuj ,pam eht dnA
,mra sih dewollof dna denrut senemoelK
yawhcra enots eht hguorht gniklaw ,dnah ni dnah
.redneg a ro seiceps a
”.retaw era yeht ,doof era yehT .snedrag ehT“
’.eurt saw nolybaB fo snedraG
”.oot uoy evol I“ ”.uoy evol I“
.egufer rehtona dettops yeht ,llaf ot nageb thgin sa ,llih a no pU  2 fo 2 traP ,emanrohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“   yojne esaelP
.niarg elgnis a ton dloheb ,etutitsed eht dna roop eht dluow siht fO"
”nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI“ ygolohtna eht ni dehsilbup saw yrots sihT
.derepsihw senemoelK
”…ti dedraoh evah dluow eh
...“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.niks mraw tsniaga niks mraW .ruf mraw dnuora depparw ruf mraW
.regnorts saw ti won tub ,revir eht ta ereht neeb dah gnilgnit tahT
”.nwodnus yb revir eht hcaer ll’ew ,emoC“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.derevocsid noos saw rewsna riehT
”sdroW eht revO hsaW treseD eht fo sdnaS eht dna...“
?ti htrow yllaer ti saW
.sdoG eht fo pal eht ot ylmraw democlew tub ,enolA
”.gnihtyna ekat t’noD“
”!laed hcus on edam I“ .delworg selcohtagA .ylwols deksa senemoelK ”?eurt taht sI
.htym a neeb evah lliw snedraG eht ,wonk lliw uoy sa raf sA
”?uoy ot sueZ ekil kool I oD“
.rehtona eno ta dekool dna deknilb riap ehT .deksa yehT
”;snedrag eht ekil hcum era uoY“
,esuohmraf dlo eht ediseb dnuorg hguot eht no drah nwod gnippord erofeb ,sdleif nworgrevo eht hguorht deklaw yehT
.teef sih ot gnilbmuts ,detuohs selcohtagA ”!oN“ .meht erofeb dessama
.daeh sih desiar senemoelK ,deifsitas yllaniF
.dehsulb dna deremmats tar ehT
.dias senemoelK ”.rucnoc I“
”!htaed ot evrats meht ekaM
.gnihtemos tnaem ti tuB
.elbisnopser si eh dediced evah yam
”.yrtne ruoy ot noitidnoc eno tub …si erehT“
.no yrrac ot denimreted
”.laets ton tsum ew ,dercas era snedraG ehT“
?tresed eht fo elddim eht ni htaed ot evrats oT
.ylsuovren deksa esuom ehT
.deddon selcohtagA
.gnissorc revir wollahs eht fo elddim eht ni ylfeirb ylno noitnetta rieht dleh ssenilnaelc fo ssenisub ehT
.ylkciuq rebmuls rieht ot debmuccus riap eht ,klaw a hcus retfA
.deppots selcohtagA .ylmrif dias senemoelK ”.ti ekam t’now eW“
.sterces s’rotsaC fo eno yreve laever ot gniog ton m’I“
.senemoelK ot revo dekool neht ,taorht sih deraelc eH
,uoy niatsus llahs tahw ekaT“
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
erehw ,knab eht ni nrow worruf a si ereht yllamroN“
,silopolagem elbram A
.meht deppots erugif eht ,htrof pets ot nageb owt eht sA ”.esruoc fO“
daeh dereves s’xof revlis eht ,ti detfil tar eht sA
.hsa ot denrub si emoh latrom ruoy esuaceB“
naht erom erew yeht spahrep tub
ebor deniur sih htiw gnilbmuf deppots esuom ehT .tsal ta dias eH
.dimuh ylthgils os reve teg ot detrats
”?gnilaets eb ti dluow yhW“
.nedrag eht ot ecnartne eht gnilaever ,edisa deppets yehT ”.doog yreV“
.siht demrifnoc lavirra riehT
.nwo sih ni sdnah s’esuom eht koot tar ehT ”?kniht uoy od tahW“
.meht dnuora detuorps seniv dna seert egraL
.delims erugif ehT
.dehctertstuo mra sih desiar selcohtagA ,ylwolS
.eno si llits ereht fI
.ti ni eulav fo gnihton dah eH
.semag yalp t’ndid sdog ehT
,won mih ot daed era uoy tuB
.htrof meht derutseg dna delims erugif ehT
.ria eht ni gnilgnit egnarts a saw erehT
ehT"“ ”.uoy dlot tsuj revol ruoY“ .deksa senemoelK
”!si eh erehT“ .ylkciuq ooT
”.emac uoy hcihw morf dlrow eht ot nruter reven yam uoy ,snedrag eht retne uoy ecnO“ .dias yehT
”.em nopu dewotseb sah ehs tahw tsuj rof tliug leef I gnihtyna fI
”.rehtegot ti od su teL“
.yltfos deksa erugif ehT
”.retne yam uoY“
”!loof a saw sixueZ dna ,ti tuoba gnihton wenk I rO“ ”…ro …ro
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.emit ni tsuj tfel yeht
.elbissopmI .oN .ti ees
.teg ot demees ti rednarg dna regral eht ,tog yeht resolc ehT
.ereh otni enog eb t’nac taht snosaer suoirav rof xetal dna xednaps ni egatrohs a desuac sah ohw
,deddon senemoelK .detseuqer selcohtagA
”.rewop sti esuba ton lliw ohw elpoep yb dnuof eb ylno nac snedrag ehT
.eurt erew yehT .snedraG ehT fo sdnegel ehT
,rehtegot kcab tnemrag sih fo strap eit ot deirt selcohtagA ”.yenruoj eht no eid ot hsiw I nehT“
.oot ereh hsaw osla nac ew ,deednI“
senemoelK dna selcohtagA ,emit tsaL
.derepsihw senemoelK
sih morf gnilgnad ebor sih fo sniamer derettat eht ,seenk sih ot esor esuom eht ,yllaniF ”…sueZ yB“
,senemoelK dna selcohtagA fo etaf eht
.tnaem lla ti tahw wonk t’ndid eH .deil eH
.derettum esuom ehT
”?uoy dluoc ,ti ssim ot sa dnilb os eb ton dluoc uoy tub ,suoudra dna gnol erew slevart ruoY“
”.neeserof reve evah dluoc smaerd ym naht lufthgiled dna lufrednow ,lufituaeb eroM“
.maertsnwod gnitniop ,dellac senemoelK ”.retaw eht
.snedraG ehT dnif ot ereh emac uoY“
”?yretsym a deniamer erusaert a hcus tey ,dnal siht deklaw elpoep ynam oS
,meht ot tsnwonkebnU
.knabrevir eht fo dum tfos eht otni nwod mih desae eh ,nehT
.gnissorc a eb d’ereht dias uoY“
.nolybaB fo snedraG gnignaH tsol eht si skniht selcohtagA tahw ot pam nelots a htiw
’.dnas eht yb dewollaws neeb dah seidob rieht
koot yeht sedirts drawno ehT
.elims a htiw derepsihw eH ”.ti ecarbmE“
,erom etsat ot gnilaeppa saw ti elihw ,dna meht fo hcae deifsitas tiurf eno ehT
.esroh tseraen eht ta flesmih delruh eh ,egar detneirosid sih nI
.deklaw eh llits tub ,dnas eht dna nus eht fo tnurb lluf eht morf
”?ssel gnihtyna od I dluoc woh ,snedraG ehT fo wodahs eht rednU
.detsetorp esuom ehT
.gnidliub degamad eht otni devrac emit siht
.meht morf deppird retaW
.revir eht fo knab eht klaw ot nageb dna esor riap ehT
.no pam eht htiw tnemhcrap fo parcs eht tuo dellup dna ebor sih fo sniamer deniur eht otni nwod dehcaer eH
.deksa esuom ehT ”?revol ym dnA“
.snedrag eht ta derats eH
knabrevir eht otni devrac emit sihT
,gnimoc saw wenk uoy htaed a morf em devas uoy rehtiE“
.delims erugif ehT .deticer eH ".niarg
.dlrow eht ni devirra dah yeht sa erab sa sdrawno deklaw esuom eht dna eH
”.ereh tuo mraf a sdliub ohw nam eht si evarB“
.derebmemer selcohtagA ,ylnedduS
.gnivieced erew skool tub ,ylmlac dewolf retaw ehT
nward niaga ecno erew seye ’selcohtagA ,sevlesmeht detcelloc yeht sA
.deplug selcohtagA ”.edirp rieht peek ot teg daed elbaruonoh ehT
.dercas si dnal siht esuaceb …esuaceB“
”.t'nseod ti oN .oN“
.srats fo snoillib eht dna nus gnittes eht ,noom gnisir eht rednu ffub eht ni rehtegot riap eht
.erutan dna stnalp ni detaoc
”?ereh ylppa swal sih dluow yhw nehT“ ”.t’nod uoy ,oN …oN“
.seye sih dniheb pu dellew layarteb dennutS
.nwo s’tar eht dnuora shgiht sih fo eno gnisae neht
,tsew htron eht ot delf dna yawa denrut srekcatta ehT
,drows sih werd senemoelK .trid
”.taht drof nac ew kniht I .peed-eenk naht erom elttil ylbaborP“
.revir eht ni detcelfer dna delkraps
.dias eH ”.ssorc nac ew ,ydaets era ew fi tuB“ .denraw tar ehT
.aicueleS fo esimed eht erusne ot gnik naihtraP eht htiw laed a edam uoy dias yehT“
.uoy ot sknaht ,nials si sixueZ“
.meht erofeb deraeppa erugif ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ezag s’esuom eht teem ot denrut tar ehT
.htaerb peed a koot tar ehT .deilper esuom ehT ”?truh uoy erA ?seY“ .ylwols nageb senemoelK ”…selcohtagA“ .mrof
noos ria ytsud dna yrd neeb dah tahW .regnorts raF
”?naem uoy od tahW“
”?taht si yhW“ .deplug owt ehT
.ereht llits saw tI .deknilb eH
.epahs eht sdrawot pets ot gnitrats
.niaga senemoelK dessik dna deddon selcohtagA ”.gniretne yb esol ot gnihton evah eW“ .delims senemoelK ”.ti desuac uoy seveileb eh esuaceb ro ,aicueleS fo egeis eht fo esuaceb rehtie
.snialp eht otno dna mraf eht tsap tuo deppets yehT
?neddih os lufituaeb os gnihtemos si woH“
suotiutarg saw noitceffA .eltneg dna mraW
.snedrag enots eht fo toof eht ta devirra dah yeht ,ti gnisilaer tuohtiW
”…desiarp eb sdoG“ .nolybaB fo
.kcas egral a nwod gniworht ,detuohs srehtnap eht fo enO
,nellaf sah modgnik ehT
doots ecnartne eht evoba ynoclab a morF
.snedrag eht nopu erew yehT
”!daeh ruoy no tcelloc ot evila tfel eno-on si ereht lufetarg eB
.erugif eht ot denrut riap ehT
.noziroh eht no duorp doots nolybaB fo snedraG eht ,sdnas gnillor eht revo ,ekal eht dnoyeB
.elpmet sih no deniart wob eht yb mrif dleh saw tub
.derepsihw eH ”.erehT“
mih tcetorp ot nolpoh ’senemoelK
.ezorf riap ehT ”?yhW“
.senemoelK gnigdun ,dias esuom ehT
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF yb
”?yeht dluow ,snedraG ehT fo gniklat snaicueleS fo riap a tsurt ot nosaer on evah dluow snaihtraP eht ,deedni dnA
.tirips ni dah won eh tnempiuqe ni tsol dah eh tahW
nelots dah I gnisilaer morf rotsaC deppots uoy dnA“
”.ereh retsaf si retaw ehT“
,retaw eht otni yltneg desae htob yeht dna desserdnu tar ehT .deerga senemoelK .detseggus selcohtagA ”.oot
.dnuora gnirats ,deilper selcohtagA ”.seY“ ”.gnissorc
.enog era seilppus ruO“ .dias tar ehT
.deksa erugif ehT
.ekal eht fo thgis thguac yeht ,enud a revO - .eurt lla saw tI
.lufitip eb dluow lairt tsrif eht ta llaf ot ,raf siht emoc dah yehT
".lla deef ot hguone ytnuob ,slatrom nopu dewotseb eb tsaef etinifni teL"
.ecnatsid eht ni snedraG gnignaH eht dna revol sih neewteb gnikool
.meht gnoma erehwemos gnidih ,aicueleS ni llits erew yeht spahreP‘ .thguoht eH
”.smelborp erom evah ew ,sseldrageR .spahreP“
.derb dah yeht erehw ot txen tsuj
…snedrag eht dnuof sixueZ fI“ .detaeper senemoelK ”".niarg elgnis a ton dloheb ,etutitsed eht dna roop eht dluow siht fO .lla deef ot hguone ytnuob ,slatrom nopu dewotseb eb tsaef etinifni teL .sbmurc htiw tfel era sdnasuoht tey ,tsevrah lufitnelp paer nem gnoma taerg
.hsaw dna ehtab ot
.no levart ot ydaer erew riap eht
derednow dah gnik naihtraP wen eht ,emit eno tA
dluoc eH .pots a ot deredduhs traeh
”.gniht hcus on stegeb dnal dehcuotnu na hcus tub
.ti hguorht elbisiv tnemides fo hctap elap a ,tuo niht ot demees retaw elprup gnitcelfer eht ,erehT
.deksa senemoelK ”?evael ew fi sneppah tahw dnA“
”?won seilla naihtraP ruoy era erehW
.derewsnanu og t’ndid sïopeC etidorhpA ot reyarp yM“
.ezag gninetaerhtnu tub desucof dna tiag citsejam a
.erutcurts enots sti morf gnilgnad sevael neerg eht ees tsomla dluoc yehT
.seye s’tar eht otni derats dna
.deddon selcohtagA ”.laer …s’tI“ .derettum senemoelK ”.ti
.yldlrowrehto dna
dna deid dah sporc ehT
fo edalb eht hguorht seilppus fo kcap s’tnedor eht gniyrrac meht fo eno
.gnik dicueleS eht sserpmi ot ti dnif ot detnaw uoy dias uoY
.ruf delggardeb-ecno dna senob yhca rieht dnuora tfos dna mraw ,seenk rieht neewteb dewolf retaw ehT
,slatrom nopu dewotseb eb tsaef etinifni teL"
.egdirb a fo dia eht tuohtiw ssorc ot evah d’yeht eno ehT
".niarg elgnis a ton dloheb ,etutitsed eht dna roop eht dluow siht fO"
.tes nus eht sa ssarg hguor dna dnas fo sllih eht nwod deklaw riap ehT
srats eht dna noom ehT
.htaed s’rotsaC tuoba kniht ot tnaw t’ndid eH
.revol sih ot denrut eH
.nus gnittes eht morf edahs eb ti gnittel
”.em evol dna em htiw yal emoC“
”.gnidnatsrednu etutsA“
”.egassem eht wonk tsum uoY“
.txet suoiretsym ot
”?em pots eh t’ndid yhw nehT“ ”.wenk rotsaC ,hO“ ”.ti
kcabesroh no srehtnap keerG delggardeb owt ees ot ekawa deredduhs esuom ehT
.riap eht dloh dna eldarc ot fi sa ,pu esor stnalp dna meht revo desae seert eht ,htap eht nwoD
.dewolpnu enog gnol dah sdleif ehT .ton saw erehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no
?revir citsym a si peed woh ,deednI
,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     .spahreP
tnereffid ,wen saw etsat ehT .tae ot nageb
.txet eht daer dna revo denael tar ehT
.niaga pu dnats ot deganam dna htgnerts sih denommus selcohtagA ”.dnal ’sdoG eht no yad tsal ruo si siht ,yleruS
.od I“ ”?em eveileb uoY“
,knabrevir eht no cinut sih yal eH
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.derettum selcohtagA
…naC“ ".lla deef ot hguone ytnuob
snedraG gnignaH ehT .dimaryp enots A
.daed si ronrevog ruoY
,nwo s’senemoelK dnuora liat sih gnilioc ,delims esuom ehT
”…nwo ruo no ereh tuo em del uoY
.tfel dah srehtnap eht kcas egral eht pu kcip ot dnas eht ssorca delbmarcs tar ehT
”…ymedacA eht fo yrarbil eht ni pam eht decalp uoY“
ylerus tub ylwols werg yeht sa snedraG ehT nopu dexif seye
.reverof tsol eb lliw nedraG eht fo seiromem ruoy ,aicueleS ot
.taht tuoba yrroS
,drawrof deppets yehT
.ronrevog nials ruoy ot detimil ton si ti tuB“
,thgil s’gninrom yB .thgin eht tuohguorht detsal etidorhpA fo serusaelp ehT
dna edisa meht gnidiug
".sbmurc htiw tfel era sdnasuoht tey ,tsevrah lufitnelp paer nem gnoma taerg ehT"
dna meht ot txen seert eht morf tiurf a dekcip hcae dna deddon riap ehT
.dekcip eb ot ydaer smets morf delgnad stiurf epir ,thgirB
.cinut sih htiw rehtob t’ndid senemoelK
,nwad eht otni deklaw yeht ,dnah ni dnah ,edis yb ediS
.noziroh eht no epahs a nopu gnitser seye
deplug selcohtagA
,lammam a erew yeht deregaw eH
.tnecs s’erugif eht fo dloh a teg t’ndluoc eh taht sesnes sih gnidoolf stiurf dna stnalp ynam os erew erehT
s’esuom eht ,noziroh yzah eht ssorca derats yeht sa dnA
,ebor sih no gnihctac tub hself s’esuom eht gnissim edalb eht ,drows sih htiw gnuws redir stI
.efil htiw duorp dna suoyoj ,gnimeeT
”…esuaceb t’ndluow ew wonk uoy dnA“
.senud ydoolb eht nwod llor ot nageb dna tuo delbmut
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.erom ecir fo niarg a ton dna
,relur remrof s’selcohtogA ,sixueZ ot layol erew ohw esoht dna
.derettuts senemoelK ”?tahw-hW“ .dog A .taht
!ecirp lufitip a seirrac doolb siH !mih tegroF“
,esarhp errazib a was
yrots s’yadoT dna
niaga ecno eh ,retlehs koot selcohtogA sA .deerga senemoelK ”.etarepsed ro evarB“
.esroh sih fo kcab eht otno ti delruh dna seilppus fo gab rieht pu dekcip dah rehto ehT
”.snedraG ehT ni reverof evil ot hsiw eW“
dah yeht fi llet t’ndluoc selcohtagA .erugif a
.toofrednu retfos dna rellat
eht rof dedaeh erew yeht taht elat s’rotsaC etal eht spahreP‘ ’.meht
.mih ta kcab erats ot demees yehT
.yawa dekool selcohtagA ”?uoy ot esle gnihtemos naem ti seoD .mraf
.stnalp dna seert neewteb spag yb yllarutan demrof ,htap a tem
.tew dna tfos won saw ruf rieht ,retaw revir eht fo ecarg eht htiW
,ssorca dehcram evah nem ynam
- ”.efil siht deretne ew sa sedaH fo esuoh eht retne ot su wolla ,tseuq ruo no sdog eht erofeb llaf ew fI“
eht otni nwod tsrif-ecaf mih gniggard
.yks elprup a rednu revir eht ta devirra yehT
.ti morf ylitraeh knard riap eht ,lavirra nopU
eveileb t’nac I“
.dniw gnirepsihw eht no stirips tnelis eht yb stnuoma taerg ni degaruocne dna
.deppord sredluohs ’senemoelK
,ruf kcalb eht erew serutaef elbabircsed ylno ehT
”?siht ees uoy nac
,kcas eht ot ,tsud fo duolc eht morf yawa detfird seye sih tub ,llits deniamer senemoelK .drows rieht
nruter ot esoohc uoy fI“
,derepsihw selcohtagA
,rekciht emaceb ytsud dna trohs ecno ,ssarg eht dna yawa desae dnas ehT
.meht erofeb reggib
.sdnah ruoy no si doolb s’aicueleS“
.delims neht ,dellum erugif ehT ”.sdoG ehT morf
,htaerb peed a koot senemoelK
eht fo doog eht rof reyarp a tsuj s’ti esoppus I ,nac I“
”.ti dnif ot elbatius enoemos rof gnipoH .esruoc fo yhW“
.eugnot s’esuom eht gnikcil
.dehgual erugif ehT
.rehtie esu on fo saw tnecS
”.llits ereht doof eb neve thgim erehT“
spahreP‘ .tekcop sih ni gnikrow neeb dah htaerb gniyd sih ni
detsisni dah sixueZ taht owt eht
hguorht dnal ehT ?ees uoy nac ,erehT“
-    .nolybaB fo snedraG gnignaH ehT otni dna
.gnik naicueleS ruoy yb flesruoy edisgnola detucexe eb ylerus lliw revol ruoy dnA
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.rehtona eno ta dekool owt ehT
.ecalp siht ni gnimoolb saw efil fo cigam yrev eht fi sA