”.asuS morf swen evah I ,sixueZ“
ylmrif esuom eht dessik tar eht nehT
.nus eht fo eye gniees-lla eht rednu enolA .ssarg yrd ehT
itiffarg tsuj saw ti derugif eH
.denworf senemoelK
”.uoy skees sixueZ“
.niaga aera detcirtser eht retne ot elba saw esuom eht ,noitcartsid taht htiW
.sevlesmeht deef ot hguone dah ylerab srenwo rieht woN
.ylmrif dias selcohtagA
.tnemhcrap eht pu dedlof ylluferac dna nwod kcab hctap eht decalp eH
dna acilisab eht fo tuo deklaw
eulav suoregnad fo gnieb
.kaerbyad ta detraped riap eht ,sdaeh
.cinut notihc kcalb a ni s’senemoelK ,ebor noitamih etihw sih ni selcohtagA ,desserd tog neht
esuom ehT .pu hsuh ot demees retaw eht nevE
,morf emoc dah yeht erehw ta kool dna kcab nrut ot deppots senemoelK ,esir eno detserc yeht sA
.thgis fo tuo saw ytic eht ,gnineve eht yB - .aicueleS fo tuo daor eht gnola yaw rieht edam riap eht dna deddon tar ehT
.dnah egral sih htiw kcab eht no selcohtagA deppals dna
,dednuofbmud llef eh tub ,ekuber ot denepo htuom s’senemoelK ”.dnal rieht ot tnorffa na sa ti ees yeht spahreP“ .detnurg selcohtagA ”.supmylO
.mrof tra na otni
”.kcul dooG“ .dekrims eH
.stseirp eht ot tfel tseb erew hcihw fo sgnilaed ,meht
.delims esuom ehT
.etats fo sriaffa tuoba yrrow ot deen on evah dluow uoy
.tenibac eht fo kcab eht ta yliddohs decalp gnihtemos ot nward saw eye sih taht llorcs eht nruter ot tnew esuom eht sa saw tI
”.em rof etaf rehtona meed yeht raelc ti edam evah sdog eht roF“
.ylwols dias selcohtagA
- ”.era snedraG gnignaH ehT erehw wonk I“
.tluciffid hcram ydaets a edam snoitaludnu dna spmub ehT
- .gniklaw no tpek riap eht dna ylitraeh dehgual tar ehT ”.si ti spahreP“
!ruonoh ym koot eH“
”.traped ew erofeb
.pil sih tib esuom ehT
”.em nioj ot emoclew syawla
.ydnas erom dna erom emaceb dnalssarg eht ,dnaletsaw eht otni rehtruf dna rehtruf devom yeht sA
,kool delzzup a senemoelK evag selcohtagA nehW
flesruoy ekil elpoep morf noisserpmi eht fo saw I“
daor siht wollof eW“
”.selcohtagA ,sraw trats ot dnetni t’nod I“
mih htiw retaw toh eht otni esuom eht gnidiug
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.klaw su teL .riaf si tnemugra
”.yrarbil eht ni sllorcs fo seires a dniheb saw tI“
tuohtiw si ti sa ksat hguone esnetni na si nem drah gnicudorP“
.su nopu llaf ot foor on s’erehT
.dloterof seye sih tahw dedragersid eh dna egarim eht ot esiw saw tar ehT
,tnemhcrap eraps emos no seton wef a edam ,tnemom a rof ti deiduts eH
.seilppus ruo yrrac ot reisae eb lliw ti dna
.debhtaed sih no lliw sih degnahc suhcoitnA litnU“
”.tseroop eht nevE
ruoY“ .deddon dna detnurg tar ehT ”.namesroh a ton tuB“
.tsae eht ot nrut eht si erehT“
.sïopeC etidorhpA fo enirhs eht dehcaer esuom eht emit eht yb krad saw tI    -    .enirhs eht ot deklaw dna pam eht htiw ymedaca eht tfel selcohtagA
”?sesroh emos erih ton ew dluohS“
remmus gnirud sulprus egral a evig ll’ti ,ti htiw daeha og ew nehW .tuoba
gnirpsffo dedaehenob sih thguat I retfa taht lla dnA
.niaga dehgual niuodeb ehT
”.htgnerts naht elbaulav erom neve si
,detnaw eh seutats rof moor eht lla evah dluow sixueZ
.tnatsid tlef rettahc fo bubbuh eldi ehT .teiuq llef riap ehT
dna llaw kcab eht sdrawot dehcaer neht
yromem eht ot decuder saw ecneserp s’niuodeb eht fo ecnedive lla sa enola doots star owt ehT .tsim tresed eht otni
uoy htiw thgin lanif eno tseuqer I“
”.naicitilop a morf sseneugav a detcepxe evah dluohs I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,eurt era selat eht fI“
.ecnagorra fo tniop eht ot gnortsdaeH
ygolohtna eht ni dehsilbup saw yrots sihT
”.ereht ekam ot sreyarp wef a evah I
”.mih kees ton od I tuB“
…mih ees t’ndluoc taots eht ,taots eht ees t’ndluoc eh fI
,serutsap hcir ro sknabrevir elitref ezies ot esuac on evah dluow snaihtraP eht
.delkcuhc selcohtagA
;egdelwonk dicueleS lla fo mus etelpmoc eht t’nsaw tI
”.selcohtagA ,ezirp rieht si htaed ruoY“ .detrons eH
.detnurg selcohtagA
ocsidorue ot xednaps ni gnicnad srumel denrut ohw ,lufraF lacsaP yb
.gnidliub eht fo tuo rehto eht gnidael ,dias eH ”.reffo gnitpmet yrev a syawlA“
.neddih saw pam eht erehw moor eht fo renroc eht sdrawot ssorca kcab devom eh
,em llet ,aicueleS rof redael detfig a hcus era uoy fI“ .dellac xof ehT ”?tahW“
.srellevart ot doof artxe lles ot desu esehT
”?emoc uoy od yhw oS“
deriuqne uoy dnalmraf ehT“
.uoy kees nem gniniamer siH
.ssyba eht retne oT  .erad A
a deciton eh sa denediw seye siH
dekool eH .mih fo retteb eht werd ytisoiruc tub
?noitavitom enivid niag uoy sa hcus nam a did nehW“
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF yb
ecno foor eht erehw rednu dna srallip eht neewteb doots dna spets eht debmilc selcohtagA .sniur eht revo gnikool
.elbat eht fo edis eht raen lairetam desunu eht fo noitces a rof dehcaer esuom ehT ”.esruoc fo …hO“
.mhtyhr on saw erehT
.tfel erew srallip fo lufdnah a ylno dna enog saw foor ehT
.pu mih wollaws ton did htrae ehT
ssendetoof kciuq taht dias evah emoS
”.ruonoh ruoy ,deednI“
”.ti fo niarg a derebmemer evah ot smees eh taht toN
,revewoH .aicueleS fo pihsronrevog eht ot rieh saw eh ,oga keew a yleraB
taht pam eht no kram a s’ereht tub ,flesti retaw eht hguorht revir dnoces eht ssorc ot evah ll’eW .yrotirret detrahcnu no er’ew ,ereht morF“
.senil thgis gnidiova ,sllaw eht ot tpek eH
”?nur ot gnideen etapicitna uoY“
,selkna rieht no yrd debbur dna sladnas rieht ta deggans ssarg trohs ehT
.flesmih ronrevog eht fo tnemtnioppa sserpxe eht no demrofrep saw hcraeser siH
lliw eW“ .detseggus senemoelK
?uoy t’ndid ,ecalap taht ni efil ytterp a evil did uoY“ .detrons tar ehT
.steerts eht otno kcab
.dlrow eht lla rof doof hguonE
htiw decalper saw eh ,emac emit eht nehw
,laets dna eveiht ot degaruocne dna desiar erew atrapS fo nerdlihC
”?ti ot emit ruoy lla etoved ot deen ton thgim uoy taht hguone detfig yllarutaN
”.nerdlihC“ .deplug tar ehT
”.thgir si yroeht ruoy fI“
.teef sih ta nwod dekool dna dehgis esuom ehT
”.edisni peels nac eW“
”-ot hguone naht erom eb lliw razzendahcubeN fo snedraG eht gnidniF“
.detrons tar ehT
,rettib dna deye-llud ,devirra esuom eht ,yad hcus enO
.wol gninnur saw yrt ot noitavitom selcohtagA dna ,drah saw ytlayol eht gnikaF
.nirg a htiw detaeper selcohtagA ”.enola era eW“
,tenibac eht fo raer yrev eht ta kcab ti decalp eH
.dewollof tar ehT
,deffocs senemoelK .pu ti gnignah dna ebor sih fo tuo gnisae
.delims senemoelK ,elzzum s’esuom eht morf tsal ta gnippilS
- ”.emit yna ta su rof emoc dluoc yehT
.tar a ot pu deklaw selcohtagA ”.era uoy erehT !senemoelK“
srallip eseht dnuora flesti parw llits yam sdog eht fo rewop ehT
.retaw eht otnI .llaf ehT
denrecnoc taht selpmet eht dna senirhs eht ni derots yllareneg erew stnemucod suoigileR
.seye sih otni derats dna selcohtagA dehcaorppa eH .dias senemoelK ”.ton evah uoY“ .dias selcohtagA
.loop eht fo egde eht no tsal ta nwod tas esuom ehT
erongi neht ton uoy dluoC
-    ”.elbaecartnu era tresed eht ni enola nem owT
”.su gnikees emoc lliw dna mih deyarteb I srevocsid sixueZ erofeb gnol eb t’now tI“ .dias selcohtagA
.wap sih devaw xof revlis ehT
.gnidliub eht fo renroc eht ni sllorcs gnimocni emos hguorht gnitros saw taots ehT .nairarbil eht ,rotsaC rof nepo eye na tpek dna gnidliub eht deretne selcohtagA
rieht nopu stemleh rieht
”?ereh tas ma I elihw ereht doots uoy era yhw
.ylwols dessap thgin ehT
,elbat ybraen a no ti decalp dna llorcs gnol a tuo dellup eH
.tsal ta dias selcohtagA ”.nelots ton s’tI“
”.erus rof ti ni nur ot elggurts ll’uoy tuB“ .dennirg esuom ehT ”.lliw notihc ruoy naht erom tol a dniw dna dnas eht morf em stcetorp tI“ .dekrims senemoelK ”.dneirf ym ,gnol erofeb noitamih a gniraew terger ll’uoY“
elbat eht no nwod ti decalp eH
.derettu eH ”.enola era eW“
”?lufituaeb siht t’nsI“
”.gnik eht fo evol eht ogrof llahs I nehT“
”.nelots si ti oS“ .detrons senemoelK
,noitacol s’nedrag eht fo wonk elpoep fI“
.elbram eht no pu mih gninioj
.snrub aicueleS“ .detrons eH ”?liated hcus ni gnihtyreve nialpxe I
.ymedaca eht rof detraped dna
.ecnanrevog dna scitamehtam
,tnelis yltcefrep deyats esuom ehT
”?erofeb detiolpxe neeb reven yeht evah yhw neht
.detfil ti litnu ,hctap eht ta deregnif eH .wonk ot dah eh tuB
dluow tI“ .daeh sih koohs selcohtagA ”.seilppus
.derednauqs ylbatius saw shtab eht ta yad suoiverp eht dna laedro na koot deb rieht
.stnavres sih fo eno ta pu dekool xof revlis ehT
.esirnus eht otni daor eht nwod gniunitnoc
?elpoep lla rof eulav fo saw noitamrofni lla taht
,snedraG ehT dnif ot sdoG eht yb nesohc eno eht era uoy fi ,yhW“
.ecneserp ruoy htiw em ecarg uoy ,yllaniF“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.ecnatsid eht otni raf
.niaga dekool eh nehw ereht llits saw tI
,ylluficreM .daetsni
stroppus htiw erutcurts nedoow llams A
?snaihtraP ehT“ .oot repaehC
,tcepser eud lla htiW !riS“
.ralucsuM .emosdnaH .eb-ot-gnik a fo seitilauq elbaicerppa eht fo tsom erob sixueZ .mih ta gnikool detah selcohtagA ,sdoG
”.llaf reven lliw aicueleS taht snaihtraP eht dnimer ot gnihtemoS
?enimaf fo ytilibissop eht dna
”.ainemrA htiw llaf daetsni ecnaigella rof serised rieht taht snrecnoc era ereht dnA“
.deffocs dna seye sih desolc xof ehT
.etufer roN .nialpmoc roN
”.oot tsae eht morf kcatta yna evivrus ot daets doog ni su tup dluow sulprus tahT
”.tuo egayov llahs ew ,nwad tsrif tA .llew yreV“ ”.uoy
sa hcus snoitcartsid
htiw neeb evah ot thgin tsal ym tnaw I ,emoh ti ekam t’nod ew dna liaf ew fI“ ”?erus er’uoY“
!ytnuob elbitsuahxeni fo ecalp a era yeht neht
.ssapsert meht tel ot deifsitas ,kcab detfaw sdniw ehT
,og em tel evah t’ndluow eH .oN“
- .evoba snevaeh eht ni enola tfel saw noom eht dna noziroh eht woleb deppord nus ehT
.dekrims tar ehT
.dnah sih htiw ria eht dettaws dna detrons senemoelK .denialpxe selcohtagA ”.ti eldnah ot hguone delliks ton esoht ot
”.em eb reven ti yaM“
”?tnemhcrap eraps yna evah uoy oD“
”?syad wef a rof enog eb lliw uoy taht sixueZ llet uoy diD“
.dnoyeb taerg eht …neht dnA .ecnatsid eht ni egdirb dna revir eht ,daor gnihcterts eht ,meht erofeB
.dnim s’selcohtagA otni dehsalf gnikaerb egdirb eht fo egami ehT
.yltnatculer dias esuom ehT
,aroga eht hguorht kcab deklaw eH
spam eht deirrac selocohtogA
wonk od I tuB .ton wonk I“
”…stnaw eh ,selcohtagA ,snedraG eht tnaw t’nseod gnik ehT“
.deilper flow ehT ”.ton od I“
.shtab eht ta ylralucitraP .ecneserp s’senemoelK ni nehw gnirednaw ot enorp erew seye s’esuom ehT
”.sraw trats ot dnetni t’ndid uoy dias uoY
.egdirb eht ssorca emoc dah yeht ,tesnus yB
.debircsa si ruonoh mohw ot nem yltcaxe ton era eW“ .deffocs tar ehT ”.ti dnif ot seno eht erew ew fi gnirb llahs ti ruonoh eht redisnoc hguohT“
.elbram eht otni devrac esarhp a deciton eh ,os did eh sA
.rehto hcae neewteb pu deldnub
.dnal yrd ,drah dna ssarg trohs eht otno htap eht fo ffo pets tsrif eht koot selcohtagA .lla ti fo ssenhsiloof ehT .od ot tuoba erew yeht tahw ta yrlever ni tnelis doots yehT .sdnal detrahcnu ehT .snialp eht otni derats riap ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”?eh t’nseod ,emit ruoy etsaw ot ekil seod ronrevog tahT
.flesmih enog evah dluow ro
.egdirb eht otno deppets owt eht sa seye sih dellor esuom ehT .detnurg eH ”.os esoppus I“
,egdelwonk neddibrof sihT“
.]resaet rehto ro regnahffilc eht evloser sretcarahc[
”.tnecifingaM“ .doots neht
.lliks taht ni detfig yllarutan era uoy taht em llet shtab eht fo sllaw ehT“
,oN .ezirp ym ton si ti tuB“
tsuM“ .dehgual flow ehT
,sredro s’ronrevog eht fo noitaloiv ni yletinifed saw selcohtagA .pu derevoc neeb dah gnihtemos ekiL .hctap
.ees dluoc selcohtagA sa raf sa dehcterts yrarbil ymedacA s’aicueleS ni sllorcs fo skcar ehT  2 fo 1 traP ,lufraF lacsaP yb
”.selcohtagA“ -ot dah tsuj eh nehT .saw ti erehT
.deneprahs ezag s’selcohtagA
.yldab taht siht detnaw ylurt yeht rehtehw tset ot dehsiw sevlesmeht sdog eht fi sA
”.ssorca edaw ot hguone wollahs s’ti stseggus
.taefed htiw dias eH
.roolf eht nopu pird ruf sih gnittel ,tsal ta doots eH
elihw gnihtemos dnuof I“
boj s’sussanracilaH fo selcohtagA saw tI
,dnuora dekool ,detloj tar ehT
...ylluferaC .eno yb enO
.eno tsal sih tsol tsuj dah selcohtagA
dna pu kcab ti dellor neht
dna daeh sih derewol neht ,desigolopa dna taorht sih deraelc eH
,yhposolihp htiw tnemhcrap hcum siht llif dluoc uoy taht yltaerg mih desirprus tI
”.ti ni erusaelp sdnif eh kniht I“
.ecnatsid eht otni gnitniop yb tar eht derewsna esuom ehT
”.ereh morf levart s’yad ruof tuoba eb ll’tI“ - ”.gnik naihtraP
,dehctaw gnieb t’nsaw eh erusne ot thgir dna tfel sih ot
.drows sih werd senemoelK .depmuj riap ehT
.erofeb naht gninnuc dna ykaens erom raf eb ot dedeen eh ,ronrevog eht fo ecarg eht tuohtiW
htap taht gnola deunitnoc ro peels ot ytic eht otni kcab yaw rieht edam elpoep sa
.etsah htiw dnA“ .tsal ta dias selcohtagA ”.drawnO“
”.dnif ot desoppus saw I kniht t’nod I gnihtemoS“
,derettum selcohtagA
.nirg a htiw kcab tas dna detrons tar ehT ”.neht no oG“
.mrif dleh egdirb ehT
.deknilb esuom ehT ".sbmurc
ylduol dehgual tar eht
”.detsaw eb ti ees dna enutrof fo reidlos a nopu ti tsurtne
.tuoba hcum os draeh d’yeht snamoR esoht fo emos nevE
tA‘ ,dias I dnA“ .dennirg sixueZ
snaihtraP eht ,sixueZ
”.riS ,detcejer neeb sah dereffo ew ecnailla ehT“ ”?ti si tahw ,seY“
.dnarg ton saw egdelwonk rof tseuq sihT .taht tsuj od ot
.shtab cilbup eht otni dna noedo eht tsap
.oot s’ymedaca eht fo noitaloiv ni osla ton fi
:secruoser rieht deloop riap ehT
.mra sih rednu temleh sih htiw dna noitamih a ni acilisab eht morf yltcerid evirra dluow esuom eht ,yad nevig a nO
.elpmet llams eht nopu emac owt eht ,gnol erofeB
.ekal eht ni retaw ehT“
,elttil tpels riap ehT .denwad yad tsal eht ,gninrom tahT
.evisnefed deniamer tar eht tub ,denetfos stnedor owt eht fo egaugnal ydob ehT
,meht tfel d’yeht sa yal sgnignoleb rieht dna ruf rieht fo ffo dnas eht tpek dah noitavele ehT .kaerbyaD - .ti
kciuq saw esuom eht ,shtab eht edisnI
”?noitamrofni neddibrof ereht sI“
.teef sih ta derats dna detnurg selcohtagA ”’.esaE
”?od uoy spahreP“ .detnurg sixueZ
.ratimics sih dehtaehs eH
”?esaelp ot ysae sa ton tsuj m’I spahreP“
dna kcar eht fo tuo sllorcs eht desae eh ylteiuQ
,taorht sih ni traeh sih htiW
.erugif ’selcohtagA otni denrub seye s’eninac ehT ”?eutats-
.sraey eht revo ti tcetorp ot deirt dah
.delkcuhc tar eht
”.doolb ruo erab sdnas eht tel neht ,ytnuob a mialc ot hsiw uoy fI“
.yawa denrut dna dehgis eH
.derats dna desuap tar ehT
kcab dna ymedaca eht ot aroga eht hguorht klaw gnol eht ekam ot dah selcohtagA taht hguone deirav dna suoudra seno tsuJ
.shtab eht dnuora neht ,retaw eht otni dekool
woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
-    .ti fo tnorf ni llorcs rehto eht tup neht
doots stnedor owt ehT
.retniw gnirud enoyreve deef ot doof hguone evah ylerab ew sdnats ti sa
!stsevrah sseltimiL
”?yeht t’nod ,serusaelp ddo evah neM“
tegrof ot detpmetta dna
!swonk eh taht gnihtyreve
sa ees yeht noitamrofni draug ohw
”?gniddib s’resinoloc ym od I dluow yhW“
daor delbboc eht no slemac dna sesroh fo dnuos ehT
.yltneuqerf meht dessap snavarac edarT
.daor eht pu deunitnoc riap eht dna deddon esuom ehT
retsam ot gnitpmetta
”!laeppa sti ees ot gninnigeb m’I
”.ymedacA eht morf pam eht eveirter ot deen I tsrif tuB“
S“ ”.eutats eht rof snalp eht htiw gnolA .worromot reviled ot uoy rof sredro noitallecnac eht evah lliw I .esae tA .dooG“
taht rof ksa ylpmis
.ytefas rof meht neewteb deldduh seilppus rieht gnipeek ,steknalb rieht nopu nwod yal yehT
.dnah sih ni tnemhcrap fo parcs eht ta gnirats
.htuos eht ot ahtamaD dna tsae eht ot asuS morF
?eb ti dluoC .pu desnet eH
.deklaw yeht snialp eht otnI
”.niaga nruter uoY !selcohtagA ,hA“
.loop eht fo edis eht no pu gnittis ,deksa tar ehT
.dnuorg rieht doots eerht llA
.denialpxe elidocorc ehT
”.sreyarp ruoy gnitpurretni rof esigolopa I“  .dias eH
dna tenibac eht ni parcs terces taht eciton t’ndluow rotsaC taht sueZ ot deyarp eH
.snoitseuq detacilpmoc deksa reven sixueZ
,oot ainemrA dna aihtraP morf stamolpiD
.noissim ruo nialpxe ot su eriuqer
.depmuj esuom ehT
.rof gnikool saw eh nosrep eht dnif ot
,sey hA“ .rae ot rae dennirg senemoelK
?taeh eht tsuj ti saw rO  ?ekoms ti saW
pu no gniunitnoc dias selcohtagA ”.eunitnoc tsum ew ,emoC .loof a saw sixueZ detseggus taht gnihtyna eveileb dluow I“ .deksa senemoelK ”?mih eveileb uoy oD“
”?em ekat yeht lliw erehw ,gninrub si aicueleS fI“ .mrif
”?uoy ekat d’yeht kniht t’nod uoy yleruS“
kcabesroh no rekciuq raf ti ekam
”sdroW eht revO hsaW treseD eht fo sdnaS eht dna...“
,ffo deird riap ehT
.rof enod saw eH .ti saw tahT ”.rotsaC olleh ,hO“
.delriws dniw ehT
.yltruc dias eH ”.eutats a ,seY“
,meht raeh ot derac ydobon fI
.selcohtagA ,uoy knahT“
”.noitazilivic fo yaw eht si detacude eb ot tahT
.dliub lufrewop ,gnorts ,ruf kraD
.esuom eht ta kool ot kcab denrut eH
.evitnecni hcus on nevig erew sussanracilaH fo nerdlihC
.dnahffo ,deksa senemoelK
,saw ti derettab dna hguor woh yb gnigduJ
”.stseretni lanrac erom sih yb nevird saw ohw nam eht yldnof rebmemer od I tub ,suoipmi si ti spahreP
,woleb retaw eht ni detcelfer thgilnoom gnisir dna thgilnus gninaw ehT
era uoY“ .delims tar ehT ”.muisanmyg eht ta ffo gnihtemos pord ot evah I“
.deunitnoc esuom ehT ”.ti fo llA
.gnihtemos rof deksa eh emit yreve
.ti dellornu neht ,esac sti morf ti desae
.sllorcs fo lluf moor eht deretne dna
.ssenredliw naibarA eht dna ahtamuD fo ytic eht ot etuor eht saw tI .ekila stamolpid dna sredart ,seimra yb desu eno ,htuos eud daor a erob sihT .llaw enots eht fo tixe nretsew eht hguorht detraped yehT .elbuort fo tuo riap eht peek dna yrt ot smra dna stiw sih esu ot saw
.ssentaerg cinelleH fo egaenil eht swohs taht gnihtemoS“
senemoelK elihw ,seilppus eht dna
.ecnetsisrep ylnO
.nwonk eb reven dluow ti
.eye s’tar eht thguac gnihtemos ,ecnatsid raf eht nI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,suoveihcsim yldrawtuo gnikool tuohtiw tey ,ylluferaC ?thgir
…saw ti fi tuB …oN
”.ytic siht fo stnemeriuqer eht ot ssecxe si dnalmraf siht
sdniw tresed ehT
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
.secneuqesnoc eht reffus dna hcaorppa ot meht dedaog
”?eh seod won ,dlrow eht fo atsiv eht etaicerppa ot erac t’nseod sellihcA fo nos A .esruoc fO“
”?huH“ .derepsihw selcohtagA
taht leef I ,hcraeser ruoy gniwolloF
.reyarp ni peed senemoelK dnif d’eh ,ti gniretnE
,noitcid dna yhposolihp fo stra eht deretsam evah ohw esoht era erehT“
.noitalupop eritne eht deef ot tneiciffus eb ot gniog llits s’ti retniw yb dna
”.oot esorp dna yrotaro
.dias selcohtagA ”.tsew og ew
.ezag rieht morf ytic eht derucsbo dnal eht fo gnillaf dna gnisir ehT
.meht htaeneb htrae yrev eht ekil pu deird noitazilivic fo sngis ehT
,uoy eb ot ti naem sdoG eht fi roF
.enoyna rof emoc nac gnihtyna ,snialp eht ni ereh tuO
.elpmet llams eht fo niur ehT
”.mulysa uoy tnarg yam ti epoh dna ylkciuq ti dnif ,kees uoy revetahW
”.egdelwonk nelots fo yoj eht si hcuS“
.delims xof revlis ehT
,nwodnus ta uoy teem lliw I ,esac taht nI“
.sïopeC etidorhpA fo enirhs eht raen
.dleh erats eht ,tnemom a roF
”nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI“
”.detneirosid emoceb ew tsel ,gnivom peek tsum ew tuB“
deerga selcohtagA
”?ma regnol on I taht yas ot si ohW“
.sixueZ ot kcab liart a dael dnA
.pam A .ti deiduts dna
dna tnemhcrap neddih eht pu dekcip eH .eciwt kniht t’ndid esuom ehT .ti ees t’ndid eh spahreP
.delbuort tlef noos tub ,deffocs tar ehT
.seye s’selcohtagA otni peed derats senemoelK ”?mih ekil nam a yfsitas ton taht thguO“
”.ecneuqesnoc on evah sdrow rieht tub ,esion ekam yehT“
eht tuohtiw ro htiW .mrots yna rehtaew nac eW
.ecnatsid eht ot gnitniop ,dias senemoelK ”.ereht revo elpmet a s’erehT“ .dessorc yehT
.ti otni gnixaler erofeb ,esirprus yb nekat gnieb rettal eht ,spil eht nopu
.delbmur senemoelK
.retaw eht ni flesmih gnigrembus retfa dias selcohtagA ”.sboj ’sixueZ fo eno gniod
.delbmurg tar ehT ”?gniht a hcus od dluow
,deddon dna detnurg tar ehT ”.roolf tresed eht evoba su peek lliw ti dna
.deliocer esuom ehT
gnikool neeb ev’ew tahw evah nac I dna uoy ,tsal ta spahreP“
.ronrevog eht fo ecarg yb esoht ssecca ot dewolla ylno saw selcohtagA dna detcirtser erew yrarbil eht fo straP
.dehgual esuom ehT
.flesmih ot derepsihw eH ”.rehcaet roop a saw I taht ees I“
,tca ot faed erew srae esoht ro
.delbmur selcohtagA ”!enim eb ot saw acilisaB ehT
”.llaf eripme s’rednaxelA gnihctaw fo yoj eht si ezirp ym
”.tsew daeh tsum ew ,woN
,tuB .tenibac eht otni decnalg taots eht nrows evah dluoc eH .rotsaC ot tnemhcrap desunu eht fo noitces a dednah eh
,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.htuos eht ot revir tsrif eht tsap nwod
sa tnatropmi saw hcihW .boj a saw tI
”.yrarbil eht fo noitces detcirtser eht nI...“
.edirts rieht noihsuc ot desufer tey
.lamron naht meht fo erom raf hguoht
ohw …sdoG“ .gnilbmurc dna nekorb yal tser ehT .tcatni deniamer edis eno no wef a dna srenroc ruof eht ni seno ehT
.tnemmoc on edam selcohtagA .detnurg eH
.toofrednu dekaerc egdirb ehT ”.spahreP“
.esac sti ni kcab ti decalp
”?gnik dicueleS eht yb detirehnier eb ot ton si tnetni ruoy epoh I
.teef rieht tsniaga gnivigrofnu dna drah saw dnuorg ehT
.thgir eht dna tfel eht ot pu gnarps smraf dlO
.snialp eht no thgilnoom ehT
.pam taht ot kcab gnicar tpek dnim s’selcohtagA ,srae sih ni gnar llits sdrow s’siuxeZ elihW
”.ti rof tiderc nekat ,pam eht ees ot dednameD
.supmylO tnuoM fo sdoG eht ni eveileb ton od ohw elpoep era erehT“
.erac t’ndid sixueZ taht meht llet ot traeh eht t’ndah selcohtagA .seye rieht ni thgirb enohs smraf wen eht fo epoh ehT
.mih eveileb ot tar eht rof semit elpitlum siht nialpxe ot dah d’eH
- ”?sdoG eht fo lliw eht noitseuq ot I ekil nam elpmis a si ohw neht
.moor eht ssorca kcab gniklaw ,yawa denrut dna mih deknaht taots eht
.sdrow sih fo gnignir eht dna
.tsehc sih otno revo dellor selcohtagA ,sseltseR
”.ylkciuq evom dluohs eW“
.deggurhs selcohtagA ”!ytinav rof ro raw rof rehtie evrats ton deen roop eht dna
ydobon demees ti
.mih dniheb elbat eht otno nwod
.deknilb selcohtagA
”.drol ym ,t’nod I on …oN“
...“ ”?yrarbil eht fo noitces elbissecca ylcilbup eht nI“
.nur a ta ,daor eht
.sdaeh rieht dnuora delttar
.egdelwonk taerg saw moor llams siht nihtiw tuB
.mih no taps tsuj dah sixueZ fi etilop erom neeb evah dluow tI
.deffocs senemoelK ”?sdog eht fo ytud eht rof s’ti won dna
.tnemhcrap fo eceip dlo yrev a tuo dellup
”.ymra yna nurtuo nac eW“
.lla ta daor on ees ot ylno
.dnas ehT .senud ehT .dnoyeb eht otni peeD .sedirts rieht demuser riap eht dna deddon tar ehT
”sdroW eht revO hsaW
”,gnikatrednu eht etiuq si ti taht dnatsrednu I“
,gnik eht fo evol eht rof saw ti tsrif tA“
deeps taerg ta detraped dna lemac sih fo snier eht debbarg eH
.tnatsissa na sa mih peek ot tif was tnemecalper sih taht gnieb noitalosnoc ylno ehT .elbatius erom demeed eno
.rof gnikool saw eh tahw dnuof eh litnu ,meht no slebal eht dennacs dna dehcraes eH
,tsae sdaeh htap eht nehW
.detsetorp senemoelK ”.nac I“
?gnitnuoc s’ohw tub ,egalloc tra na yllacinhcet ,lleW
.gnorts era eW“ .deffocs sixueZ
,emit ’sixueZ no egammur ro stseretni lanosrep eusrup ot ton saw eH
.pu ti dloh ot revir eht otni nwod
.nolybaB tuohguorht gnur spetstoof fo seohce ehT
.denoitnem uoy ”hcraeser ylralohcs“ taht deirt I“
.htaenrednu decnalg eH
.redlo nehw sreidlos sa elbatius erom eb ot sa
treseD eht fo sdnaS eht dnA“   yojne esaelP
,elpmet eht tfel dna sgnignoleb rieht derehtag yehT
.repsihw a ta dias esuom ehT ”.enod si tI“
.ereh rewols saw ssergorp riehT
- .eurt erew esimorp sti fi naem dluow ti tahW
.deplug esuom ehT
.lemac a edirtsa ,ratimics a dna dleihs a gnidloh ,sebor ni depparw ,flow A
.ti kees ot derad eno fI
dna dnah rehto eht ni drows ,mra s’tar eht ot depparts nolpoh a htiW .yrnopaew eht ,esac ’senemoelK ni dna ,gnihtolc eht ,retaw eht ,eraps ot dah yeht doof eht
.mih derussa senemoelK
”.sterces esoht fo nrael I taht tif ti nees evah sdog eht taht
.ereh peels dluohs ew spahreP“ .saw
”.derewsna neeb tsuj dah reyarp yM“
.niuodeb a ,meht erofeB
...“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.tcejbo t’ndid esuom ehT ”.erus m’I taht fO
.sbmurc htiw tfel era sdnasuoht tey ,tsevrah lufitnelp paer nem gnoma taerg ehT"
.sllorcs rehto eht gnicalper erofeb ,ebor sih ni ti tup
.deknilb selcohtagA .deksa taots ehT
.niaga tar eht dessik dna ecnatsid eht desolc esuom ehT ”.spahreP“ .elims kaew a evag neht ,dehgis senemoelK ”.rof
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.I ro uoy ekil nam a ton tuB“