.ecnelis ni ereht doots eH
”!pit rallod ytfif a ,ekil si sihT“
.ekoms fo duolc a otni thgir deklaw eh sa elzzum sih fo tnorf ni wap a devaw netsE
,reffo ot sah efil tahw fo tseb eht ecneirepxe ot
.lautcnup s’ohw yug a ekil I
,ssenisub ym ton s’ti ,kooL“ .ffo deliart eh
.rof ezigolopa ot gnihton evah uoY“
.ylkciuq emoc ton did gninrom txen ehT  .dehgis dna
.ylsseltroffe snalp sih etucexe dluow eh emit sihT
.esuap evitalpmetnoc
stfig esoht erahs ot woh dnatsrednu yad eno yam uoy taht sepoh eht ni
,gnihtyna yas ot ,kaeps ot detnaw eH
,egnahc eht revo dednah yltneitap netsE
.derugif eh ,ydaer teg llew sa thgiM .evif-ytrof xis
”.kciuq ti ekam dna ,tolreM esuoh eht fo elttob a evah ll’I .retsiM
.mih tel ton dluow sthguoht sih dna dnim sih tub
”?uoy t’nera ,gniht elttil gnimrahc“ gnirettum
.yad erom eno tiaw ot evah tsuj dluow stcartnoc gnitnuocca siH
.ralloc sih xif ot netsE gnivael
.detsetorp netsE
.gnihton otni ylkciuq gnidaf
,desoppus eh ,reisae eb thgim noitautis ehT
yeroC fo espmilg a thguac netsE yad txen ehT  2 fo 2 traP
.denrut dna deppots yeroC
.sterces tsepeed ruoy meht htiw erahs ot dna
.eeffoc gninrom sih netsE evres ot yppah naht erom demees ohw ,retnuoc eht dniheb enola gnidnats
”.taht rof etal elttil a sti tub ,ezigolopa ot u tnaw I
.rethgirb tib elttil a steg yad eht ekil leef I
.sgel s’netsE neewteb tser a ot emoc wap sih gnittel
”.rac eht ni em tselom ot deirt eh retfa emoh klaw mih edam I dnA“
thgit ti dehctulc dna
,tpada ot desoppus saw eH
...leef I ,uoy dnuora m’I nehw taht wonk od I tub
.dnatsrednu yeroC ekam dna yrt ot
stnap s’netsE deppiznu eisseJ ”.ereh
.dnah s’yeroC dezeeuqs netsE
s’netsE nwod dna pu wap a gninnur
”?knird ot gnihtemos uoy teg I naC
”?uaeb wen ruoy tuoba tahW“
!tobor gnikaerf a ru ekil gniklat potS“
,sdradnats lamron yb evitcartta ylbidercni
.tekcop sih morf syek debbarg netsE ”.erus ,haey ,hO“
.evirra ot eniw sih rof gnol tiaw ot evah t’ndid eisseJ
.retsaf klaw ot detrats dna yawa mra sih dellup eH .dessih yeroC ”,og teL“
.elbat rieht gnihcaorppa saw ohw stnap sserd kcalb htiw
.yrassecen ton tub
.retsiger hsac eht no ydaer eht ta sregnif sih ,pu kool t’ndid yeroC
”.nosrep retteb a eb nac I ekil leef I ,uoy htiw m’I nehW
.wodniw eht hguorht xe s’eisseJ ot kcab gnikool ,deksa netsE
.ria eht ni pu smra sih werht eH
”?eiteewS ,emoh ta selbuorT“
.gnitrilf fo mrof rehtona eb thgim siht gnisseug
.serutarepmet lanretni sih ni esir a tlef netsE dna
.uoy fo duorp os ma I dna nwo ruoy no stiart eseht fo lla htiw laed ot woh gninrael er’uoY
.rotinom sih rednu morf pu til enohp siH
?gnorw saw tahw oS .rewsna emas eht mih evag tnempiuqe lanretxe ynA
demialcxe eisseJ ”!tihs ,hO“
ffo dewohs taht trihs-t kcen-V knip a dna
,noitcnuflam ot dengised t’nsaw tI
”!suoiralih s’taht ,netsE hO“ .eciton tuohtiw meht neewteb ecnelis eht gnirettahs ,rethgual otni tuo tsrub eisseJ
.nwod dna pu mih dekool dna
.taht ekil thgin a retfa deneppah reve gnihton ekil gnitca ot kcab eb dluow u serugif
,gninrom txen eht pohs eeffoc eht ot snruter netsE nehw dna emoh flesmih klaw ot sreffo yeroC
.fo devorppasid yltaerg netsE taht gnihtemos saw mih dnuora esle enoyna rof drager fo kcal siH
.daeh sih ni deohce sdrow s’rehtaf sih sa
”.remrahc a hcus s’eH ?netsE dneirfyob wen ym tem uoy evah ,riamA“
.yas ot esle tahw erus t’nsaw eH ”.erus ,haeY“
,ti rof dellac noitautis eht nehw segareveb dna slaem emusnoc ot dengised neeb dah eH
;tuo ti erugif dluoc I taht gnipoh saw I tub ,wonk t’nod llits I taht tol a s’erehT
”.retteb hcum os od nac uoy ,gnilrad em morf ti ekaT“
”,dnatsrednu t’nod I“
.ffo nrow dah stceffe eht litnu tiaw ot evah dluow sksat renif dna delddum emaceb cigol dneherpmoc ot ytiliba siH
.tluciffid ...si gnitpadA
elggig rehtona evag eisseJ
dehsinav dah xof eht enifed ot demees taht sgniht eht fo llA
.gninnalp sih ni ekatsim evarg rehtona tey edam evah thgim eh taht denrecnoc
.sthguoht s’netsE otni depees noitartsurF
,ni dnelb ot ,evitcejbo niam sih ni deliaf dah eH
.siht ekil soiranecs tuoba mih thguat dah koob gnitad eht ro efil sih ni gnihtoN
.netsE ot kcab gninrut ,wap a devaw dna deffocs eisseJ
,devirra yeroC litnu setunim eht detnuoc eH
.nosrep nI“ ”?ti si tahW“
”.uoy htiw od ot erom gnihtyna tnaw t’nod I
.pu elkcub ot dlot erew uoY“
.elims netsE edam namow a sa eisseJ fo aedi ehT
t’nerA ?ydaerla gnillac ,netsE yeH“
.ffo evord dna rac eht otni tog yeht sa nirg sih edih t’ndluoc eisseJ
.uoy llac ot saw detnaw I lla ,taht lla retfA“
.eiteews no emoc ,wA“ ”.efas ton s’tI“
specib denot ylthgil sih fo trohs tsuj deppots seveels eht dna ruf nworb fo tfut thgil a
.gninrael ,snoitidnoc thgir eht rednu ,dna gnitupmoc fo esoprup eht rof dengised neeb dah ti ,mih ekil hcuM
,eisseJ dna netsE htob fo tnorf ni meht tes dna sessalg owt htiw tuo emac revres ehT
”?olleH“  .reve naht regnorts won saw yeroC llac ot egru eht tub ,yhw nialpxe t’ndluoc llits eH
,rehtaf ,mih evol I
”.enil eht pu gnidloh er’uoY
.roivaheb ddo tnecer s’yeroC dna
uoy morf gnimmargorp ruoy fo strap dih I
,won mih ot esnes ssel neve edam gnihtyrevE
,ekoj a ta tnih eltbus a spahrep ,delggig eH ”?thgir ,uoy nO
.suolaej yllatot s’eh ,mih tegroF“
.emoclewnu yrev dna hguor saw pirg siH
”?thgin tsal tuoba klat ew naC“
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb
.ti rof hcaer dluoc revres eht erofeb kcab ti deppans ylkciuq eisseJ hguoht ,detaes erew yeht ecno yawa unem eniw eht devaw netsE
.ecnahc eht nevig ,dnim sih egnahc dluow eltsimocac eht depoh tub ,gninnalp saw eisseJ tahw fo aedi doog ytterp a dah eH
.thguoht eh ,yletairporppa tca ot woh wenk yeroC
.tuo dettuj ti sa gnalc hsrah a dna
.ekil eb dluow eltsimocac eht htiw setad erutuf tahw no detcelfer eh elihw deddon
,ytisoiruc larutan dna sessecorp gninrael ruoY
.yad yreve mih llet ot erus ekam I dna
,tnaruatser eht ot kcab daeh sih denrut netsE ”.os yas uoy fI“
,kaerbtraeh dna evol tuoba hcum os denrael ev’I
.gnicneirepxe morf deretlehs neeb ylsuoiverp dah tub
,gnitca neeb ev’uoy yaw eht gnitca rof nosaer doog nmad a evah uoy sselnU“
.yeroC ,dnatsrednu ot tnaw I“
.yenom ruoy tnaw tnod I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ereht yllaer ton saw terref eht taht flesmih ecnivnoc ot gniyrt fi sa
.elbmurg a htiw smra sih dessorc yeroC ”.ecnahc dnoces A“
,lanif noisiced eht ekam ot thguoht dah netsE erofeB
.kcab wap sih dellup yeroC ”.esaelP
railimafnu ,tneiciffeni saw tI
”?noH yako ,esle gnihtyna deen uoy fi llac a em evig lleW“
.elzzum s’xof eht tsniaga spil sih desserp
.daeh sih koohs dna delims toleco ehT
.dnatsrednu t’ndid llits eh sgniht rof mih ot ezigolopa ot
,nosrep nwo ruoy otni worg dna ytirutam hcaer dluow uoy taht dnim ym ni noitseuq on saw ereht ,revewoH
.skeew wef tsal eht ni flesym tuoba tol a denrael ev’I ,kooL“
.wap ni sehsid owt htiw ybraen yldrawkwa gnidnats saw navE
.detaeper eh ”,uoy llet ll’I“
.pissog ytirbelec dna noihsaf erew snrecnoc ylno s’eltsimocac eht hguoht ,netsE morf tupni elttil htiw kaeps ot yppah deraeppa eisseJ
daeh sih koohs netsE
,meht evol uoy meht llet ot liaf ton od
ma54:01 4102 ,82 yaM  .selbairav ynam ooT
dapeton sih no nwod gnihtemos etorw toleco ehT
.tuo tup ll’yeht dna ,pu tuP
.sselesu saw egassem eht
.noitartsurf sih etipsed ,elims mih edam tluser ehT
”.noitceffa dewohs eno woh saw taht thguoht I“
”?noisses ’pu mraw‘ elttil a ot yas uoy od tahW
”,rof gnizigolopa er’uoy tahw wonk neve t’nod uoY“
.rood eht tuo yawflah ydaerla saw eisseJ tub ,dednopser diletsum dexelprep eht ”,ti tog I ,haeY“
,nwod daeh sih tup eh daetsnI
.elzzum sih no elims a fo tnih tsethgils eht htiw ezag s’netsE tem yeroC
.yaw sti no ti tnes dna egassem eht demrifnoc eH
”.tuoba klat ot gnihton s’erehT“
.boj etauqeda na gniod ton saw eh
,spollacs dna retsbol sih otni gud liatgnir eht drow rehtona tuohtiW
.neeb dah yeroC htiw etad sih retsasid tnerappa na tahw gnirebmemer
retnuoc tnorf eht ot yaw sih gnikam ,pohs eht ot rood eht hguorht dehsup netsE
”?netsE ,tnaw uoy od tahW“
.denoows eisseJ ”,rac eciN“
,nwod deid dah noitautis eht fo taeh eht ecnO
.thgin eht otni ffo nar dna denrut eH
,ssenisub sih ot kcab denrut enilef eht don a dna elims a htiW
.edisni neeb evah thgim thguoht netsE gnihtyna morf yrc raf a ,edisni repap fo pils enol a saw erehT
,kcab llup t’ndid yeroC nehW
.mih dnuora dlrow eht fo tser eht ekil tsuj
depmuls sredluohs s’yeroC
sredluohs s’enipluv ehT
”?taht saw lleh tahw ,netsE“
.mih fo tnorf ni srepap fo elip eht revo wap sih gnivaw
,enola era uoy esuaceb uoy ot tneserp ym denepo ev’uoy tbuod on evah uoY
,pu gnuh dah yeroC taht sngis rof denetsil netsE
.yawa decnuob dna
.tleb sih no gnikrow detrats dna
.dnah ni efarac a htiw retnuoc eht dniheb morf tuo deppets yeroC
denruter toleco eht taht neht ylno saw tI
,ssalg s’eisseJ deruop revres eht sA
.seralg yrgna sih hguorht detrotsid dna delknirw serutaef sih
.thgin eht rof egrahcer ot moordeb sih ot tnew dna
ylisaenu liat sih detfihs yeroC
”?thgir lla gnihtyreve sI“
.eeffoc eht gnikat erofeb detats eh ”,stnemegnarra wen ekam ot dah yltnecer I“
”?ris ,redro ruoy ekat I naC“
.esle enoyna ro netsE sdrawot ragluv neeb reven d’eh
.lla retfa yats ot yeroC ecnivnoc ot elba neeb t’ndah eH
deunitnoc eisseJ ”!sruoh rof klaw t’now uoy ,raed ,tnemtrapa eht ot kcab teg ew nehw uoy ot od ot gniog m’I sgniht ehT“ .tnemgdelwonkca ni deddon dna sselehtenon delims eH
.netsE ot denrut dna
.thgir sgniht ekam ot ,dnatsrednu ot rewop sih ni gnihtyreve enod dah eH
.og tel reven ot dna ti otno dloh ot
,yhw nialpxe t’ndluoc eH
”.og dluohs uoy kniht I“
.ot desu teg dluoc eh gnileef a saw siht ,revewoH
.tuoba liat sih gnihsal dna yddig saw eH
.netsE ,doog eb retteb dah sihT“ .devirra yeroC
”?eituc ,sruoy ro ecalp ym oS“
etavitca ot ylno dengised erew taht
yeroC tuo snrut tI
.tluassa lauxes thginot did uoy tahw llac yeht eveileb I“
.nigeb ot ydaer si yenruoj ruoy snaem siht gnidaer er’uoy taht tcaf yrev ehT ,netsE
?tpeni os eb ylbissop eh dluoc woh
.enola dna tsol ,riahc retupmoc sih ni tas eH
.mra s’yeroC debbarg dna drawrof dehcaer netsE ”!evael t’noD“
.flesruoy rof efil ecneirepxe dna pu worg uoy ees ot teg reven dluow I
.redluohs eht no hsup lufyalp a netsE evag eh ”,yoc eb t’noD“
.netsE dniheb mrof ot nugeb dah enil a litnu tnelis saw yeroC
.netsE morf ecnatsid sih gnipeek llits ,kcab deklaw yeroC
?ecaf sih no kool eht ees uoy diD“
roiretxe nialp ylgnitnuat sti dna
”?emosdnaH ,nalp eht s’tahw oS
.tndluow u sseug I“
.netsE ta ecnalg gnoledis a gnikat
.nekorb tlef eh erehw
hguorht ,did netfo elpoep sa elgnim ot
”.hsulb flesmih nataS ekam dluow taht sgniht od ot gniog era I dna uoY“
,dnuora er’uoy nehW“
,eton eht devomer eH
”,uoy llet t’nac I“
.rof gnizigolopa eb ot desoppus saw eh tahw tsuj rof ,thgin taht gnorw enog dah tahw tuoba kniht ot deniarts eH
.trihs sih morf selknirw eht dehsurb eh sa dias netsE ”,oN“
,retnuoc eht dniheb gniretiol
.deilper netsE ”.uoy knaht ,seY“
efac eht morf uoy rab tnac i
”!emoh em evird ot detagilbo era uoY“
.dediced eh ,ti od dluow eH
.tfel dna deretne elpoep sa gnihctaw yb emit eht dessap netsE
.suoixna ylgnisaercni mih gnikam eno hcae
.dnim on netsE gniyap dna selbat nwod gnipiw
,sesnes sih detlusni ti won tub ,erofeb tnacifingisni os neeb dah tI
.noitautis eht ot dnopser ot sselpleh
eht ot dnopser ot desoppus saw eh fi erusnu ,dednopser eh
.draobhsad eht htiw etamitni emoceb dah taht
.ronaemed pot-eht-revo esiwrehto s’liatgnir eht fo tuo nellaf dah msaisuhtne eht fo emos tub ,deerga eisseJ
detxet riamA“ ”—wonk t’nod I“
.yklis dna suoiruxul ,enohs ruf siH
”?thgir ,llib eht tog ev’uoY .ekoms a deen I ,naM“
,enodnu yal sksat
.ylthgils ylno tub ,gniyl saw xof eht taht
,erom gnidaer niA detsetni er’uoy fi dna
.ssik tsrif a retfa etairporppa eb dluow noitasrevnoc fo dnik tahw erus ton ,pmirhs deirf sih no dehcnum netsE
.enil rehto eht no ylivaeh gnihtaerb yeroC raeh dluoc netsE
.reganam eht sa mih dezingocer terref ehT
.detapicitna naht tluciffid erom saw hcraes ehT
.yb evord taht srac wef eht dna spmalteerts yb ylno derewop ,etalosed dna teiuq saw thgin ehT
.lla retfa ,eniw emos evah dluow eh dediced netsE
?mih ot gnineppah saw tahw oS .siht fo yna rof demmargorp neeb t’ndah eH
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb ”selbairaV“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.sih ni swap s’yeroC koot dna
rennid ta ti tnaw tndid I
.taorht sih deraelc yeroC
,yawa llup ot deirt netsE
.detaeper eh ”,yrros m’I“ ”?tahW“
.rethgual-kcom fo dnuos eht edam eisseJ ”?sussiM eht rof dnA“
.sriatsnwod pohs eeffoc eht ta hsur gninrom eht fo dne eht gnikram
.yawyna eceip emit sih ot gnikool flesmih dnuof eh ,emit eht fo erawa syawla saw netsE hguohT
.gniklaw detrats dna netsE morf denrut yeroC
.rehtaF ,uoy ssim I
.eulav yratenom yna dloh dluoc eman sih woh erusnu ,deilper eh
.hcaer s’netsE fo tuo ti llup ton did eh tub
tnemgduj sih deduolc sthguoht elitsoH
derettam ti fo enon ,rof demmargorp neeb dah eh tahw fo sseldrager dna
edis ot edis morf spih sih devaw eltsimocac ehT
,yawa gninrut erofeb deppil-thgit yrev gnipeek elihw
.nos ym ,efil fo tfig eht htiw uoy sselb I
.tnemeticxe sih niatnoc ot elba ylerab ,rac eht sdrawot kcab mih deggard dna
;esnopser evitcejbo yletairporppa na etalumrof ot tseb sih deirt eH
,yako t’nsaw gnihtyreve fi eil ot nosaer on dah liatgnir eht gnirugif ,flesmih ot deggurhs netsE
.noisacco eht rof desserdrevo ylthgils dekool netsE
.ytitnedi eurt sih laever ot ,gnimmargorp sih tsniaga gniog netsE tuohtiw ton—
.ti nepo ot emit thgir eht eb reve dluow ti nehw wonk ot yaw on dah netsE
.citamelborp emoceb ot gnitrats saw ti dna ,tnetsisni saw eltsimocac ehT .denaorg netsE
.yawyna yojne yllaer t’ndluow eh doof hcum oot gniredro ni esnes on saw ereht tub
”,tcefrep ton m’I wonk I“
.esiwrehto tiaw ot nosaer on dah eH
tleb taes sih delkcubnu dah eltsimocac etanimeffe eht evird eht otni setunim eviF
liatgnir ylbbub a htiw efac a nopu emac eh keew taht retaL
,llet dluoc eh tahw morF .ni dnelb ,elgnim
.semit fo tseb eht ta tluciffid erew elpoep fo smotsuc eht tub ,dnatsrednu ot detnaw eH
.elbat rieht no eye na peek ot kcab gnicnalg ,flesmih desucxe ylteiuq
dehguoc toleco ehT
netsE ot denrut xof etihw ehT
”.tnaruatser eht tuoba yrros m’I“
?emoh yaw nwo ym dnif
.gnitad fo tra eht ni seiduts sih etelpmoc lliw netsE woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.emoc dluow gnihton tub
”.esaelp lluf sretrauq-eerht ,eeffoc muideM“
”,etad ruo tuobA .yrros m’I“
,yb dessap raguoc ykcots ,trohs A
.slautir gninrom sih ot satsirab wen niart ot emit hcum os koot ti dna
.enil rehto eht no esuap a saw erehT ”.yrros m’I“
ksed sih no enohp eht tfel eH
,deknilb rosruc ehT .sucofer ot egami eht dewolla dna
.etad deliaf suoiverp sih taeper ot ton dediced dna snalp gninid sih revo yeroC htiw dah dah eh elbuort eht derebmemer netsE
.s’yeroC hcuot ot tuo dnah sih dehcaer netsE
.yrt ot dah eh ,liaf ot demood erew stroffe sih fi nevE
tniop eht ot flesmih detaeper netsE
.ereh tog ev’ew tahw ees s’teL“
,enoemos laiceps taht dnif uoy dluohS
sdrow neewteb ni deddon ylpmis eH
”.uoy ot klat ot tnaw t’nod I“
”.enif sdnuos taht ,haeY“
yromem citedie sih fo pleh eht htiw nevE
.redlof rieht otni kcab srepap sih delffuhs netsE
taht dnatsrednu ot gninnigeb saw eH
.thgin tsal etad sih gnirud em
.ti rof ereht t’nsaw xof eht fi
,oN“ ”?retal kcab llac I dluohS
,deiduts dah eh tpecnoc a
.reziteppa rellams a rof detpo eh sa derugif netsE ,ecnedicnioc ylpmiS
.noitacinummoc fo sdohtem suoirav eht tuoba denrael tsrif eh nehw
.xob eht denepo dna hctal eht deppop eH ”.ti htiw lleh oT“
troffe na ni retupmoc sih otni flesmih deggulp netsE
,redro ot emit emac ti nehW
.yteirav detsehc-talf eht fo namow a rof nekatsim eb dluoc eisseJ ,ecnalg a ta ,taht desoppus netsE ,tnemmoc s’revres eht rof sA .gniyap eno eht saw eh ecnis ,morf gnimoc eb dluow pit a fo kcal siht erehw desufnoc saw netsE
.dellortnoc regnol on eh taht
etad deliaf eno sih fo sthguoht ot derednaw dnim sih
ot evah I taht em gnillet er’uoy won dna draobhsad ruoy otni em mals uoy tsriF
”?yrassecen taht fo lla saW“
,taes s’revird eht otni revo gninael saw dna
.pirg sih htaeneb dekcarc doow eht litnu
”!retsiM ,em htiw lacinhcet teg t’noD“
”.emoh yaw nwo ruoy dnif uoy tseggus I ,thginot elbuort erom yna tnaw t’nod uoy fI
.yaw rehtona eb ot dah erehT
.eunitnoc ot netsE rof yltnatcepxe gnitiaw ,tnelis saw yeroC
.noitasucca na naht eno evitisiuqni na fo erom neeb dah noitseuq ehT
.ti teg tnod yllaer U“
eno emoceb ot ydaer era uoy snaem ,snoitome ecneirepxe ot ytiliba ruoy htiw gnola
.thguoht eh ,yaw eno ylno s’erehT
.raeh ot demees netsE ylno taht yaw a ni
,roivaheb namuh fo epocs detimil s’netsE htiw nevE
.lufsseccusnu neeb sah gnitad fo tcejbus eht otni noitarolpxE –
.secnalg gnoledis gnikam mih hctac ot deganam terref eht tub
,eisseJ ot kcab dekool eH
.rorrim weiv-raer sih ni liatgnir eht gnivael ,evord netsE
,uoy dengised I nehw taht wenk I
.noihsaf ralucitrap yna ni slewov fo gnirts detagnole
,sgel s’terref eht pu deliart sregnif s’eisseJ
.elzzum sih otni pollacs a deffuts eh sa elggig ot deunitnoc eH
.morf gnimoc saw noitome fo esnes siht erehw erus t’nsaw eh hguoht ,’htrim‘ sa gnileef eht dezingocer eH
.htiw railimaf saw netsE taht dnik eht ton tub
nettirw ylnommoc d’eh esarhp hsilgnE nommoc a gnizilitu kcab etorw eh
,elbat s’netsE hcaorppa t’ndid eH
.thginot gniod eb thgim yeroC tahw ot daetsni gnitfird dnim sih
pu dekcip dna retupmoc eht morf flesmih deggulpnu eH
.yllis ,enif si siht
”.ezigolopa dluohs I ekil leef I“
.skooB goD daB yb ,5 raoR rof noissimbus a sa yrots siht etorw ohw
.ecnatsissa yna dereffo meht fo enon tub ,segap eht hguorht deppilf eH
,noitcerid lareneg s’terref eht ni ekoms welb dna dehgual liatgnir eht sa
.edistuo doots yeht sa meht fo owt eht tuoba denrecnocnu yletelpmoc demees eH .detaes erew
.lla retfa etadidnac tcefrep eht saw
.enohp taht pu gnuh yeroC tnemom eht dehsurc eb dluow
.gnitad dna pihstruoc
htiw lufhtuom tsrif sih dehsinif netsE
.yllanif ,deilper eh
wap sih devaw liatgnir eht tub ,egnahc etairporppa rof tekcop sih otni gud netsE
”.netsE ,ti nepo ot nehw wonk ll’uoY“
.em ediug ot uoy fo htob eht tuohtiw ti enod evah t’ndluoc I dna
.egnahc s’terref eht koot eh sa edis eht ot dna nwod dekool eH
.noitcerid s’netsE ni worbeye desiar a gniworht
,detatiseh netsE
”,no tleb taes ruoy tup esaelP“ .gel
.delevorg ev’I dna dezigolopa evah I
gnid duol a htiw noitasrevnoc eht detpurretni reward hsac ehT ”.uoy htiw
.eisseJ no sucof ot ,niaga ecno ,decrof saw eH
”.emit fo etsaw a saw ereh gnimoc wenk I“
elims ylbbub s’eisseJ dehctam tI
rezalb rehtael a ni xof etihw wons a ot denrut won saw noitnetta sih tub
.yeroC fo ffo seye sih gnikat ton
”.netsE s’ti ,yeroC“
tcaer dluoc yeroC erofeb dna drawrof deppets netsE
,pu deppilf liat s’eltsimocac ehT
.mih fo tnorf ni retnuoc eht no eeffoc gnimaets s’netsE tes eH ”.ereh ni gniklaw emac sruoy sa etuc sa gum a fi rebmemer yletinifed d’I
,dnuora dellor kcolc’o thgiE
,evol ecneirepxe ot nrael lliw uoY
mra eht yb netsE debbarg eH
;hctaw sih ta dekool dna nwod enohp eht tes eH
,krow ot nwod tas eh revenehw tub ,sksat ynam sih fo eno tsuj etelpmoc ot yad eht tuohguorht deirt netsE
.yrgna dna deracs
.noitasrevnoc eht etaitini ot woh erusnu ,stekcop sih ni sdnah sih htiw doots netsE dna
”.uoy tceffa snoitca ym woh fo gnidnatsrednu retteb a ot em sgnirb ekatsim hcae tuB“ .dedda eh ”,tol A
”?flesruoy naht rehto enoyna tuoba erac u oD
.egassem eht fo ytilanif eht dootsrednu eh
.srotpecer eson etaciled sih pu gnizzuf
,krad eht ni sbats llits erew esehT
deredisnoc neeb evah tsum liatgnir eht hguohT
”?gnineve siht rof owT“
.gnilbmert saw ydob s’netsE
esimorp I tub ,noitcnuflam a gnicneirepxe era ro
.mih raeh dluoc ybraen stnemtrapa eht ni elpoep eht erus saw eh taht hguone duol detuohs eH ”!uoy llet ll’I“
”!ereh morf selim si esuoh yM
.mih nevig dah rehtaf sih xob nedoow llams eht htaeneb yltcerid
”—ytilibaborpmi lacitsitats a si nataS“
.stnemevom eltbus dna elims eltneg s’yeroC ot nosirapmoc ni delap ti dnuof netsE
,deknilb netsE ”?tahW“
.ssik detcepxenu na otni drawrof mih gnillup ,ralloc eht yb netsE debbarg dna
”,dnah rehto eht no ,yot yob ruoY
.uoy gnivres eno eht eb lli kniht t’nod tub
.woble sih ta bur ot tsehc sih ssorca mra na gniyal ,ffo deliart eH
.enod saw eh retfa llew litnu noitasrevnoc ta tpmetta elgnis a gnikam ton
.ti dias eh sa emahs fo tnih a htiw dekcilf srae siH ”.ynapmoc ...dah I
.pu ydit ot emiT .moor kcab eht otni
”!naem uoy tahw wonk t’nod I“
.dnatsrednu ot nigeb dluoc eh hguone drah thguoht eh fi tub
.uoy dnuora dlrow eht htiw
.esuap gnol rehtona saw erehT
drawrof deppets netsE
.edis eht ot ffo gnikool elihw delbmurg eh ”,ot desu I“
.ti saw siht erus saw eh ,etad tsrif a no od ot ton tahw no nossel a reve saw ereht fI
.taerg sdnuos renniD“
.snoitacificeps esoht fo enon gniteem saw eisseJ dna ,cilbup ni gnitca rof srennam detpecca ylnommoc dna
,netsE htiw tcatnoc eye gninruter ton
,siht fo gnah eht teg ot gnitrats saw eh erus os saw eH
.deddon ylpmis eh os ,taht ot yas ot tahw erus t’nsaw netsE
.retsiger eht fo sedis eht deppirg yeroC
!uoy fo evren ehT“ ”.tuo teG“
?ereh dnuora wen uoy erA .uoy teem ot eciN“
dnatsrednu dluoc yeroC taht yaw on saw erehT
,emit tsal eht naht rennam lausac erom a ni deraperp saw netsE ,dnuora dellor ytriht-neves emit eht yB
”.ti s’tahT“ ”?ti s’tahT“
.efac eht fo tuo dna ni ylsselmaes deretlif ciffarT
”?huh ti staht oS“
,noitasrevnoc s’eisseJ no desucof gnipeek seussi dah eh
elbatrofmoc kool ton did taht snaej thgit-ruf gniraew
,won meht ta gnikool selbat fo rebmun eht ot dnuora dekool netsE
sdrow otni tup ot deirt netsE
.sriatsnwod rodnev eeffoc eht tneuqerf ot
.psag a htiw kcab dellup xof eht erofeb spil mraw s’yeroC fo gnirekcilf
,etad suoiverp sih ekilnU
srosnes sih no ezah tnasaelpnu na tfel tI
,og tel yllautneve eisseJ
.citehtapa dna tneiciffeni ,wols
”.draeh I ,uoy ffo spil sih peek t’ndluoC
”,tnetsisrep ylniatrec er’uoY“ ”.haeY“ ”.oS“
etad tnerappa sih dna riamA erehw elbat eht ot gnikool
,txetnoc tuohtiw tub ,semit elpitlum egassem eht dessecorp netsE
.enituor gninrom sih ot ecneirepxe elbarovaf
”,netsE“ .delggig eh
.denifernu dna deggaj stnemevom s’liatgnir eht ,niaga dezeeuqs wap siH
.enog dah thgin rieht woh ta rettib llits ylsuoivbo ,yeroC taps
.srotpecer egami sih desolc dna
,esuoh eht no s’tI“
skrow reilrae sih fo eno ot gninetsil yojne uoy sepoh eH
.yadot od I tahw gniwonk tuohtiw tca na hcus fo snoissucreper eht dootsrednu ylurt evah reven dluoc I
”.s’onailatI ekil ecalpemos fo gnikniht saw I“
.sthguoht sih otni tperc tbuod fo dees ehT .t’nac uoy tuB
.wodniw eht tuo gnikool elihw derettum eh ”,haeY“
.pley deniap ,duol a htiw draobhsad eht otni liatgnir eht gnidnes ,sekarb eht no depmots netsE
.elbat eht no nikpan eht dessot dna spil sih depiw eH
.doirep gnitiaw tes a saw ereht erawa t’nsaw I“
”,uoy htiw thgir lla eb dluow taht fi ,rennid gnikniht saw I“
.noitautis eht rof etairporppa leef t’ndid ti wohemos tub
.rood eht ot denrut netsE sa derettuts eh ”,yeh—H“
”.od ot em tnaw uoy tahw wonk ton od I
.won ti tnaw tnod I dna
meht fo erutan railimafnu dna war eht ,tlef dah eh snoitome eht dellacer netsE
”.uoy ot pu ti ekam em teL“
”.neves-ytrof rallod a eb ll’tahT“
ffo wohs ot hguone tsuj pu denepo kcen ehT .snaej eulb dna
”,eno regae eht ew
”.efil ecin a evah
.ecnanetniaM nuG dna gnitaD fo trA ehT
.gnorw enod ev’I tahw dnatsrednu ot tseb ym enod ev’I“
.senituor-bus krow sih etelpmoc ot
.gnimmargorp sih rof tnaem ti tahw dna
,yeroC ot klat ot saw tnemom taht ta detnaw eh gniht ylno eht tub
.doolb dna hself erew eh fi sa lohocla dna eniw ecneirepxe
.pal sih otni ylbatrofmoc liat sih gnilruc ,taes regnessap eht otni depmuj liatgnir eninimef ehT
.enoyna ot terces ym laever ot reven em demmargorp uoy yhw won dnatsrednu I
.tnetsisni saw pirg s’eisseJ tub
.xof eht esaeppa ot hguone eb thgim taht gnipoh ,dias eh
.emit rehtona gnitad fo tpecnoc eht tisiver dluow eH
.tcaer ot woh fo erusnu saw eH
.liatgnir eht fo hguone dah dah eH
”?gniog ew era erehw oS“
.wols ti ekat s’tel tub ,thgirlA“
.yeroC htiw tcatnoc-eye gnikam dna
”.revo si etad sihT .melborp ym regnol on s’taht ,emoh gnitteg rof sA
,diordna na saw eh wenk yeroC fi
.liatgnir eht ta nwod decnalg netsE
ydob sih fo strap eht ta gnibbur erofeb
keew a ni yeroC nees t’ndah eh gniredisnoc ,tnavelerri saw tI
.etteragic sih no yldeticxe deffup eh sa rof dellac noitautis eht naht deticxe erom raf demees eH ”?gniddik uoy erA“
”?eituC ,uoy pleh I nac woH .eisseJ s’eman ym ,iH“
.noitartnecnoc fo kcal sih rof nosaer rehto yna fo kniht t’ndluoc eH
,dne no gnidnats saw riah s’liatgnir ehT
.senot derepsihw ,hsrah ni tub ,ekops eH
.drawrof pets a koot netsE
.edis eht ot ffo detnac srae sih htiw llit eht ta nwod dekool yeroC
saw erehwesle ecivreS
.yas ot gniht thgir eht ekil dednuos ti tub ,tnaem taht tahw wonk etiuq t’ndid eH ”.etelpmoc leef I .tnereffid
,desoppus eh ,esnes lacigol erom edam tI
.mih rof gnitiaw saw flow desserd-llew yllauqe na erehw tnorf eht ta muidop eht ot denruter eh
,gnitad fo seicacirtni eht tuoba elttil wenk eh hguohT
,elbainednu saw xof eht ot tnemhcatta elbacilpxeni siH
.retnuoc eht dniheb morf deteerg trihs nottub etihw a ni toleco na
”.netsE ,siht od t’nac I“ .kcab deppets yeroC
.selbat ybraen yna fo yaw eht fo tuo ylluflliks htrof dna kcab gnikcilf liat sih
.llew seog ti taht yarp I dna
”.doog yna si egakcap eht erus ekam ot ’yub uoy erofeb yrt‘ a ekil fo troS“
.ronaemed citegrene dna
54:9 4102 ,02 rebmeceD  ”.wols
hcrep sti morf xob eht debbarg eH
.derettum yeroC ”,trats a s’tI“
”.dluow I“ ”!t’ndluow uoY“
,nekorb era uoy taht kniht yam uoY
.raed dloh uoy elpoep eht htiw
tuhs rood rac eht demmals dna tuo deppets liatgnir ehT
.nosaer dna cigol deifed did liatgnir eht gnihtyrevE
”.emosdnaH ,thgie ta pu em kciP
,lliswodniw eht htaenrednu seceip lareves otni dedolpxe esuom eht sa derettacs seirettaB
,tnatropmi denmad os xob eht saw yhW
.detcepxe naht renoos gnimuser eb ot dluow gnitad fo yduts sih taht demees tI
s’yeroC rednu dessarrabme ,yawa dekool netsE
.yeroC morf saw egassem txet ehT
.smra sih ni deldarc sunem eht dah ydaerla eH
.tcatnoc eye ekam t’ndid yeroC ,netsE evres ot tuo emoc did eh nehW
.flesmih dedulcni taht dna ,dluohs ti sa gnitca eb ot demees gnihton tub ,tnatsnoc saw emit wenk eH
.deneppah tahw ydemer ton dluow seigolopA“
,trohs erew sesnopser s’netsE
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.uoy htiw eb ot tnaw llits I ,deneppah sah taht lla fo etips nI
.owt ni sriatsnwod saw netsE
.ecnesba sih deciton srekrowoc sih nehw devil-trohs saw epacse siH
.dennalp sa og t’nseod gnineve rieht nehw retaw toh ni mih sdnal atsirab lacol sih htiw etad s’netsE ,emit tsaL
”.gnihtolc ruoy deniats taht eniw eht gnisahcrup rof ecnanep sa gninaelc yrd ruoy fo erac ekat nac I
.emoceb dluow uoy denigami I nosrep lufrednow a tahw dna
.detimil saw snortap rehto eht ot rettahc sih dna
.nirg a htiw deltsihw eltsimocac ehT
,euqinu a hcus dedivorp xof eht nehw eunev wen a gnisoohc tluciffid saw tI
,gnihtyreve mih llet I yad eht eb lliw samtsirhC taht dediced ev’I
sthguoht htiw deugalp gnieb saw netsE dna ,dezinagro t’nerew srepap
”.yhw wonk t’nod I dna uoy tuoba gnikniht pots ot elbanu m’I
”.gnissim s’eh tahw wonk ot mih tnaw I dna rood eht hguorht deklaw tsuj xe yM“ .deralg eh
feirb a desnes eH
”?yrros m’I“ .noisufnoc emos
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”selbairaV“   :yojne esaelP
.hgual suovren a htiw dias yeroC
.yldaorb dennirg dna
srae sih fo ssenikrep eht dna
”,tnemetatsrednu na s’tahT“
,pit ruoy seog erehT“
.desufnoc dna detaefed
.evlos ton dluoc eh elddir rehtona tey htiw mih gnisaet
”.setunim neetfif ni pohs eht ta em teeM“
,denoitseuq raguoc gnissap ehT
”.ti nepo ot nehw wonk ll’uoY“
”!elpmas elttil a gnitteg tsuJ“
”.gnivrats m’I ,tae s’teL
”.uoy ees ot tnaw I tub ,etad ruo gnirud deneppah tahw dnatsrednu ylluf t’nod llits I“
.tnatsid nworg sah dna rennid ot evitpecer ton saw yeroC tnapicitraP
.pu dessem ev’I dnA“ .derettum yeroC
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab dekcilf srae s’netsE
.ti ekil leef t’ndid erus eh tsael ta
.eeffoc gninrom sih rof seunev gnignahc ni tseretni on dah eh ,yraid sih ot yrartnoC
.knird ot gnidneterp elihw noitom decitcarp taht ni eeffoc sih gnippit
.lla ta efil on ekil demees xof eht tuohtiw efil a wohemos tuB
”?huh ,yadot yad ysuB“
”!tiaW“ ”—revo si noitasrevnoc siht nehT“
,yawa dekool yeroC hguohT
.gnieb eritne sih dedoolf ssensuovren dna noisnet elbabircsednI
.hteet sih tirg ot mih desuac dna
muroced sa hcus sgniht tuoba erom ylbaredisnoc wenk eh
?gninoitcnuflam eh saW
.noitpircsed ruoy tem taht enoemos htiw xe sih was eh em dloT
”!suolaej yllatot saw eH
,noitseuq eht fo tuo saw mih gnillet tub
”?emas eht leef ton uoy oD
?won lavorppa ym rof etarepsed os uoy era yhW ?tahw em lleT“
.gnimoc terref eht was eh nehw moor kcab eht ot nur ot kciuq saw xof eht tub
.gnitca neeb ev’uoy woh nialpxe yllaer t’nseod taht tub ,netsE yrros m’I“ .erats suoludercni
,elzzum sih no elims eht ,liat sih ni kcilf citegrene eht—
.skrow erutuf yna gnitsop eb lliw eh erehw
.dnuora eb ot tnaw ton did eh taht enoemos gnimoceb ylkciuq saw eisseJ tub ,mih edisni dliub ot gninnigeb erew taht sgnileef eht ebircsed yletauqeda t’ndluoc eH
.enituor laicos gninrom sih otni etaroprocni ot elacol wen a gnidnif tneps erew syad wef txen ehT
.wol depoots srae sih htiw roolf eht gnola delwarc seye siH
.elbanialpxenu dna elbignatni demees noitanalpxe eht hguoht ,dnatsrednu ot gninnigeb won ylno saw eh tahw
;rof uoy demmargorp ev’I tahw si sihT
.ti od ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc eh tub ,yas ot yldab detnaw eh sgniht erew esehT .doolb dna hself ton m’I .diordna na m’I ”.erofeb ti tnaw t’ndid lleh sa erus uoY
.diordna eht ot yrassecen demees naht tsehc erom
,retfa yltrohs deraeppa liatgnir ehT
.hgis a htiw deggas
,sllaw eht ffo deohce eciov siH
dna nwod setalp eht tes toleco ehT ”.uoy knahT“
.mih fo tnorf ni unem eht denepo eh sa navE ot delims eH ”.esaelp ,retaW“
”.gniod er’uoy tahw pots esaelP“
.retiaw ruoy eb ll’I ,navE si eman yM“
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb ”selbairaV“
.erofeb dah eh sa kcab eht ot taerter ton did eh
.evif ta ffo m’I ,kooL“
,uoy tuoba leef I woh nialpxe ot woh wonk t’nod I ,yeroC“
.rehtaF ,uoy morf edisa enoyna htiw meht tneps ev’I raey tsrif eht eb lliw ti dna ,gnimoc era syadiloh samtsirhC ehT – MA
egap yrruFoS sih gniviver no gnikrow yltnerruc si eh
”,eman ruoy em llet ll’uoy fi ylno tub
,gnol rehtona saw erehT
.tfel yeht erofeb mih ot dias dah navE dna riamA htob tahw tuoba kniht tub pleh t’ndluoc netsE
.ngised s’rehtaf sih ot detfarc neeb dah taht
elbarovaf eb regnol on yam ti secnatsmucric tnecer ot euD
,rebmun eht denimaxe netsE
,erofeb elims a gnirud drawkwa tlef reven dah netsE
.nikpan a fo kcab eht no nwod rebmun sih etirw ot gnol hguone ylno tub ,desuap eisseJ ”,hO“ ”.oN“
.rac s’netsE fo eton koot eh nehw denediw seye s’eisseJ
.gnilaid erofeb stnemom wef a rof rebmun eht detcepsni netsE
”.thgin taht deretnec-fles yletelpmoc erew uoy tub ,suovren er’uoy taht teg I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dnuora dellor kcolc’o evif nehw ytpme ylraen saw pohs ehT
,ydegart ni dedne yletamitlu dah etad rieht hguoht nevE
.ydaer t’nsaw ylpmis dlrow eht ,ton ro gnimmargorP .flesmih dlot eh ,ydaer t’nsi dlrow ehT
.seye s’xof eht otni derats eh
.railimafnu dna hsrah snoitcelfni eht
enohp sih otni elbac ecafretni llams eht deggulp eH
”?retal kcab emoc I dluohS“
.esiwrehto ni drow a teg ot ecnahc a dah netsE erofeb pu gnignah eisseJ morf kcilc a saw erehT
efac eht edistuO
netsE”.elgnis gnieb naht sgniht esrow era ereht tub
.noitome war fo snoitacifimar eht eldnah ot hguone derutam dah uoy nehw
?ti nepo ot dewolla eh t’nsaw yhw dna
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
sredluohs sih fo gurhs a htiW
”,nemeltneg ,gninevE“
.sserdda ym uoy txet ll’I !taerG“
,retal sdnoces owt-ytriht dna setunim nevelE
.lla retfa devlovni yllacitnamor emoceb ton meht fo owt eht taht
.retrohs gnitteg saw segassem neewteb yaled ehT
.feilebsid ni hgis a dehtaerb eh sa
,revewoh ,did yrtiucric siH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,tnemtrapa sih ot kcab deklaw netsE
.ylsselwalf dessap stset lanretni sih fo lla ,dekcehc eh nehW
xob eht ta dezag eH
ksed sih no esuom sseleriw eht gnibbarg erofeb tnemtrapa ytpme eht ot detuohs eH
”.tnaruatser eht ta uoy no desopmi I dna ,uoy ot netsil t’ndid I“
.etarebiled dna luferac meht gnikam
,ylluferac dehctaw netsE
”.uoy ees ot tnaw t’nod I“
.edistuo deppets eh sa nirg a ot denrut elims siH ”.si ti ,seY“
,revo dekool netsE
noisserpmi eht netsE evag noitatiseh s’yeroC
.gnitirwdnah s’rehtaf sih saw elbbircs eht taht gnivresbo
”?taht fo lla llac dluow uoy revetahW“
:troffe tsal eno ekam ot netsE rof emit eht saw woN
.sthguoht detcartsid morf derraj
.erehwyreve ruf gnilf ot gninetaerht
,snortap eht fo tser eht gnomA
,sdrow sih dewols dna liatgnir eht ot dekool eH
?gnitartnecnoc emit drah a hcus gnivah eh saw yhw os
”.erofeb etad a no neeb reven ev’I“
.tnaruatser eht hguorht detanoser taht hgual llirhs a htiw
”?dnim ni evah uoy did nuf fo dnik tahW“
.etad tnerruc sih ot ralimis morf raf saw xof eht dna
.retupmoc eht ta kcab derats dna nwod koob eht tes eH
:ssem a erew senituorbus siH
,dnim s’netsE ni detaeper sdrow ehT
gniraeppasid erofeb seitud etunim tsal emos htiw flesmih deisub yeroC
.elggig a htiw dias eisseJ
,hctiwt dna yletaidemmi esnet selcsum s’xof eht tlef eH
.dnuof eb ot erehwon si yeroC
.elzzum sih tfel yeht sa noos sa sdrow esoht gniyas detterger eH
”,netsE s’ti ,iH“ ”?ooolleH“
”.uoy llet ot deen I gnihtemos evah I“
.llac eht detanimret dah taht
.meht fo owt eht neewteb dekool eH
,elims a htiw dias eh
.unem eht no gniht evisnepxe tsom eht dekcip dah eisseJ
,dednemmocer saw lausac-ssenisub erehw tnaruatser nailatI rellams a saw s’onailatI
.elpoep rehto evresbo od I“
.gnimmargorp sih tsniaga dna
.deggeb eh ”,esaelP
.mih dniheb efarac eht ot revo decnuob dna
”...lla retfa ecnahc dnoces a uoy evig tsuj ot em tcepxe uoY“
dnah s’toleco eht otni sllib fo lufdnah a dekcut netsE ”.sknahT“ .niaga mih gniees ot drawrof kool t’ndid ylniatrec eH
.erofeb sa reppihc sa tsuj saw derewsna taht eciov ehT
.ffo erew yeht dna raeg otni rac eht werht eh os
dnah sih ni repap eht delpmurc netsE  .selrahC ,evoL
”?huh ,nuf laer emos evah dna ecalp ym ot kcab og ew yas ayaddahW“
.elggig a htiw dias eh
”.ecivres tnellecxe eht rof uoy knahT“ .delims dna
.msaisuhtne sih htiw gniliec eht hcuot dluoc taht srae—
.eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo eisseJ ot dekool navE
enog saw ot demotsucca nworg dah netsE taht elims lausu s’xof ehT
.liatgnir suoixonbo eht rof ”tuo gnittup“ ni tseretni elttil ylgniraps dah netsE tub
.gnimmargorp sih fo eroc yrev eht tsniaga tnew yeroC gnilleT
.etarebiled si noitisnart siht taht
;regna saw liatgnir eht sdrawot tlef eh tahw
,tlef eh ,esoprup ylno siH
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab desserp srae sih dna yllis tlef eH
”,ynnuf gnihtemos dias uoy ekil tca tsael tA“
.ot naem t’ndid eh hguoht ,derepsihw eh
”,ssenisub dehsinifnu fo tib a tsuJ“
.dnoces-tilps a rof deremmihs mih erofeb deraeppa taht steehsdaerps ehT
eet flog deralloc ,naelc a ylno gniraew
.llaw a tsniaga ti gniworht dna
.rood s’eisseJ ta gnivirra retfa txet kciuq a tuo tnes netsE
.pis rehtona koot netsE