”,raeD ym ,teem ot esle erehwon s’ereht yrros m’I“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
”?em ot siht evig ot droffa nac uoy erus uoy erA .egaw ym flah htrow eb tsum ti tub ,suoegrog s’ti
.ega dna yad siht ni luferac oot eb reven dluoc eno tub ,erus saw eh taht fo ,ti draug dluow enotselccE
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.delims ekooH .dekniw xof ehT
,hO ?tekcol A“
.ssik a rof ni elzzum sih gnignirb erofeb erom ecno seye s’revol sih otni dekool ekooH
,denediw nirg siH
,ylkeem deddon dna pu dekool xof ehT
,taoc retniw kciht a ni denword tsomla ,tfel sih oT
mih htiw eb dluow eH .eerf eb
.niaga ecno gnimrof sraet ,revol sih fo seye eht otni derats xof ehT ”!!etsah ekaM“ .moor eht fo renroc eht ni wodniw a ot detniop ekooH ”!kciuQ“
,ruf sih htiw tcatnoc edam dum fo sluftsif tsrif eht ,retal sdnoceS
.mih ot txen deb elbuod eht no gniyl xof ehtil eht ni detseretni erom raf saw eh tub ,rood eht dnoyeb draeh eb dluoc ytrap samtsirhC-erp a fo yrlever ehT
;raeD ym ,em rof yrrow ton oD“
.stnap sih otni kcab rebmalc ot tfiws xof eht
.erised htiw dellews traeh sih dna
ygolohtna syadilwoH yppaH eht ni dehsilbup tsrif
eno siht piks esaelp
.noolas eht morf dekrab eciov a
,epirtsepuL flowkcaP yb
.etsahc ti tpek hcihw sgnical eht no yltneg gniggut
.yrtnuoc eht ni ecalp sih ta rehtegot enola
”5271“ si
”,niaga uoy ees lliw I nehw ton wonk I tub
,detresni ylbicrof erew sdnah sih sa doow eht ffo decnuob kcen siH
,triks sih nwod dellup eh sa denediw seye s’ekooH
”5271“   yojnE esaelP
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT morf
.tfig siht tpecca ot uoy ekil d’I ,ereH“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
liat a fo pit etihw eht was eh ,teef sih ot mih derehsu yeht sA
,deunitnoc eh ”,wonk uoy dnA“
xof sih ta kcab dekool eh
.sserd suonimulov sih fo tekcop eht ni dehsif eh sa dias eh
”,hcum os uoy knahT .uoy knahT“
.dniheb raf ton hsif eht dna
.decitonnu og ton did taht rekcilf a
”.uoy fo daeha efil ruoy fo tser eht evah uoy elihw
.ecalp otni ylmrif ti gnippans erofeb dnuora niahc eht depool eh ,deretsam ecnO
.roolf eht ot mih gnikconk
*** ”.uoy ekil tsuJ“ .dias eh ”,lufituaeB“
.htuoy sih ni siht ekil ecalp a neeb reven dah erehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
”?etats siht ni uoy ot od yeht
.kool retteb a teg ot eye na denepo eh ,ylevitatneT
”,epirtsepuL flowkcaP“ yb ”5271“ saw sihT    .lla fo tneserp samtsirhC tseb eht saw taht dnA
,samtsirhC morf skeew eerht eb llits yam eW“
.thgileldnac eht ni dlog fo tnilg a thguac eh sa depsag xof ehT
.deddon dna ylmraw dennirg ekooH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
tiurf nettor eht
swap railimaf owt ees dluoc eh
lliswodniw eht revo edils
,moor eht otni degrab
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.nrubyT ot uoy gnidnes meht fo thguoht eht raeb tonnac I“
.eruza railimaf a tem seye sih dna ,pu dekool eH
.hsulb ot mih gnisuac
.epacse sih tneverp ot derettuhs yltfiws flah pot eht htiw
esarhp eht gniraeb kcen sih dnuora gnuh saw ngis a sa deoob neht dna dereehc dworc ehT
.pu uoy dloh ylno llahs dna eritta siht ni nur tonnac I
.dnoyeb erutnev derad ohw esoht ot gninraw a
.ssenkrad eht otni edaf dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,nrecnoc fo rekcilf a dewohs ecaf sih tub
,syadiloH yppaH
.ruoh na rof moor siht dah eH
”.raeD ym ,emit txen litnU“
.psalc eht htiw delddif ekooH sa drawrof kcen sih gninarc ,deddon xof ehT
”.elirbef tahwemos neeb sah etal fo erehpsomta eht tub
”?uoy rof no ti tup I llahS“
;seye s’ekooH otni repeed derats xof ehT
,resserd eht no top eht ni tneugnu eht pu gnikciP
.skcots eht otni dehsup yltneloiv saw daeh sih erofeb sniahc sih fo gnisaeler eht draeh eh ,noitommoc eht hguorhT
uoy rof gnihtemos yub ot detnaw I
,esuoh yllom eht edistuo draug doots yrollip ehT *** .eerf saw eH
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,reduol werg edistuo selffucs ehT
,epirtsepuL flowkcaP yb
yrots s’yadoT dna
.rekihhctiH flowereW ,floWcaM boR yb daer
yoj sih ,demaeb xof eht
”.ereh sdneirf gnoma er’ew tsael ta tuB“
”.tnetni lacitimodos htiw tluassa fo emirc eht roF“
.eerf eb ot gnitiaw
.krowidnah sih gnirimda ,kcab devom eH
.yawa mih gnirehsu erofeb elzzum s’xof eht fo pit eht dessik ekooH ”!!woN !tuo emoc
setartsigam eerht sa hctal eht didnu eH
,tnemegduj rieht morf yawa dna bom siht morf yawA
”.efil ruoy rof nur tsum uoy yas I nehw em tsurt dna
.kcab sih dniheb ylprahs swap sih gnillup ,decnuop yehT
,keew lla siht rof gnitiaw neeb dah eH
.delims dna trosnoc sih fo seye eht otni dekool ekooH
,skcirt gniyalp neeb evah yam dnim siH
.nosaes eht fo syoj eht etarbelec ot
,gnivil detrats tsuj ylno evah I tub ,gnol devil evah yam I
”?goD etimodoS eht ,eh si erehW“
,llew eb lliw lla yas I nehw em tsurT
,elzzum eht no xof eht dessik ekooH
.eye sih fo renroc eht ni gnimrof raet a
.dlog fo tnilg tniaf a was eh erows eh tub
.secnayevnoc rieht diova ot niaga nwod gnikcud erofeb seye gniworran hguorht bom gniyab eht ta dekool eH
”!ssap em tel - ereht ni s’eh wonk I“
,ti teem ot nwod derednaw wap s’ekooH
dluow eh worromot dna ,samtsirhC erofeb yad eht saw tI
,deb eht ffo devom eh sa taocittep sih detsujda eH .kraps lufhtuoy sih fo enon tsol dah eh tub ,sraey ni redlo eb yam eH
.gnioob dna gnissih dworc eht fo yticoref eht yb kcaba nekat saw ekooH ,egduls eht hguorht degdurt eh sA
.ecnecsipucnoc rieht morf elpuoc eht gnitloj
.sehceerb sih fo ssenthgit eht yb deyarteb lasuora s’xof eht ,nwod decnalg eH
,htnom eht fo dne eht ta em tisiv nac uoy lufepoh llits ma I
dnuora dekcilf seye siH
.rood eht ot pu edorts eh ,sserd sih tuo gnihtoomS
.laiceps erew uoy wenk I
.deb eht no ylivaeh nwod tas eh sa dias eh
.tekcol a gnipsalc
.emit lanif eno dekcol saw rood eht gnirussa
,esuoh ela eht ni uoy tem tsrif I ecnis revE“
”.yb em rebmemer ot
elihw ,yad eht sa rettib sa saw seye rieht ni ssenrettib ehT
lliw tahW ?droL ym ,uoy fo tahw dnA“
.ecnetnes tsal eht fo ytniatrecnu eht yb ylthgils detniat
- hcterw uoy ,ereht ni er’uoy wonk I“
.spohs eeffoc dairym s’nodnoL fo eno dniheb ylteercsid dekcut gnilenap doow dedaf fo moor a - ’lepahC ehT‘
.nrom rebmeceD psirc siht fo ecnecseiuq eht ekorb stlusni rieht
.rood eht no gnidnuop a yb nekorb ylno ecnart eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY