”?evol ,dnim ruoy no gnihtemoS“   .spil sih gnittew
.bur a ti gnivig yltneg
rediw neve euqisyhp sih ,taoc nworb yvaeh a erow god ehT
,gninrom yadrutaS ylrae saw tI
.efac llams eht ni tnasaelp dna looc ytterp
.kcid s’tac eht fo pit ytevlev ,tfos eht gnirovas emit sih koot samohT
,selkna sih ta nwod deloop stnap siH
,ton si tuo gnimoC
,dias ffitsam eht”,hhU“
hcuoc eht no wap eno sih
,sregnarts fo snoitpmussa eht htiw ytitnedi-fles
yllihc saw ria ehT
,kcar a morf gnuh taoc nworb A
s’erehT !03:6 ylno s’tI“   .moordeb rieht morf emoc nway duol a draeh eH
.enohp sih gnikcehc ,deilper ffitsam ehT ”!ees s'teL“
,god.ecioveht ta
”.tem syug uoy fi ti evol d’I
.teef sih ta gaw liat s’moT tlef eh sa gnirrup
…yag …erom eb dluohs
,tuo enohp sih dellup eh sa taoc sih ta deggut dna dnuora dekool eH
.nwod dna pu ffitsaM eht gnikool ,deilper nayrB
.traehteews a s’eH !llats siht pu tes em depleh ekaJ“ .dias reed ehT
lwem tac eht draeh eh sa deggaw liat siH .tils
,elzzum sih fo egdirb eht ssorca yal kcid s’tac ehT
”.keew siht eb ot desoppus si noitatoR“
daerps erew sgel kciht sih dna
.oot uoy rof ydaer einaeb a evah ll’I dna keew txen yb porD“
.nirg yhs a moT evag ehS
.elppin sih bur yldi ot
.ylireehc mih ta kool lrig terref gnuoy a was dna ,denrut moT ”!iH“
.guh gib a tac eht evig ot edis rehto eht ot revo tnew ylkciuq reed ehT
”?dnetta ot dnim ni stneve yna evah uoy lleW“
,dekael ti sa mih ta thgir gnirats pit knip eht
”.em tius yllaer t'nseod wobniaR“
.meht revo dewolf taht ria dloc eht morf gnitcarter sllab eht
.tac ybbat eht deciton eh sa noitingocer ni ediw werg seye siH
tfarcidnah dna
,moor eht hguorht deklaw tevic yltrop A
”?samohT ,ereht uoy …yeH“
.wap sih gnivaw ,dias ruhtrA ”!nayrB“   ”?ytrA“
.mih dniheb noihsuc egral eht no kcab gninael daeh sih
.redluohs s'samohT no daeh sih gninael ,dehgis eH .edis
tnemtrossa na ni derevoc spit reltna sih ,pohs eht dennam reed nael A
s’ruhtrA dnuora mra sih tup eH .mih htiw eruces dna tnetnoc os dekool eH .mih edisni pu dellew taht htmraw a ffitsam eht gnivig elzzum sih no elims tfos a ,tnetnoc dekool tac ehT .klaw ksirb eht morf yvaeh ylthgils shtaerb sih
”.krow ta gnihtemos fo thguoht ylneddus tsuJ“
.yadsendeW siht nocedirp eht ot gniog fo gnikniht saw I“   .deksa ruhtrA
”,mhmmM“  ”.detrats ev’uoy tahw hsinif ot uoy rof ecin eb d’tI“
.ti ot txen einaeb deruolocitlum deriuqca ylwen eht htiw edistuo yad gnol a retfa gnitser
.eson sih fo ssenlooc eht ot gnitsartnoc kcid eht fo taeh eht
.daeh s’god eht puc ot nwod gnihcaer
.kcab gninael ,dias ybbat eht ”,os yas uoy fI“
htiw ycavirp ot thgir
,hcuoc eht no nwod dehcuols ruhtrA
”,niaga gnihtyreve demeht wobniar htiw dellif eb ot gniog era spohs eht dnA“
”.sehsinav ti erofeb ti ekat ot deen I .siht gnilles er’uoy eveileb t'nac
”.evol ,uoy knahT“ .kcab delims god ehT
.yllufthguoht gniwehc ,deilper god eht
”!kool ,hO .taht esoohc syawla uoy yhw nosaer a s’erehT .spahreP“
”!lwob eldoon gge taht tnaw I
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.guh rieht ekorb yeht sa deilper ruhtrA ”!yrB taerg s'tahT“
.einaeb deroloc ylthgirb sih gnitsujda
I* .kcud dettink a pu gnikcip ,dias ruhtrA ”!eno siht rebmemer I“
tac ybbat a dna eh sa ikayat a no dewehc samohT .sgab
,kcid s s'ybbat eht fo pit derevoc eht tsniaga debbur eson tsiom ,dloc siH
,nageb ffitsam eht
.stnapucco eht yb derongi erew kcans dna eivom eht htoB
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.esolc mih llup dna tsiaw eht yb tac eht barg ot tuo dehcaer eH
.tac ybbat eht no gnisucof seye sih ,dias elbat eht fo edis rehto eht ta ffitsam ehT ”!hO
.daeh sih no polp mraw gnihtemos tlef tac ehT
.tekcop taoc sih morf retaw fo giws a koot dna
.edis rehto eht ta moor gnivil eht ot noitanimulli tnacs gnidivorp
”,eno taht dekil uoy wonk t'ndid I wA“
yal nrocpop lemarac netae-flah fo lwob A .swodahs gnitsac
.srodnev eht ssorca gnikool ,deilper ruhtrA ”,sgniht wen wef a was I“
.ti htiw nwod nikserof eht gnillup ylwols
”,uoy tius seod tI“
.elzzun eht otni gninael
.hcneb eht dnuora gniog ,derewsna tac eht
gninrom ehT .enohp sih gnikcehc ,dnuora detfihs eH
”!tohs a ti evag dna ereh tols a tog yllaniF“
.neht ti peek ll’I“ .delggig ruhtrA
”.ffeJ rof ecnanetniam hgih oot saw I“
”?hguone yag ton m’I kniht uoy oD“
.dnekeew eht rof tuoba dna tuo erew stneduts eht fo tsom sa
.flesmih ot delworg eH
.ylireehc dias terref eht
”!stink ruo fo emos gnilles yrt ot dediced yllanif I dna retsis yM“
”,eromyna rof ecaps evah t'ndid ew krow dlo si ti fo flah lleW“
,don llams a dna elims gib a meht evag eH
.tellaw sih rof dehsif ruhtrA sa dias reed eht
semitemos sseug
.tsurht thgil a spih sih gnivig dna erom ecno kcab gninael
I” .thguoht eh sa elzzum sih fo edis eht ot kcid eht gnippat
.sllab dna tfahs s’tac ybbat eht neewteb tops eht dehcaer eh sa dehgis eH
,gnolefil su fo tsom rof ,ssecorp a si tI
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,yltneg dias ruhtrA ”,moT“   ”.lla si
.erusaelp ni htaerb peed a gnivig tsehc sih ,yliksuh
,oggodneP yb ”erutseG llamS A“
!erus ekam ot retteb llits
”?tahw-W“  .deksa samohT
,moor krad eht ni no denord noisivelet ehT
.tekram dnekeew eht nwod deklaw yeht sa einaeb deroloc wobniar eht fo tuo gnikeep srae sih ,dias ruhtrA
s’tI“  .llah eht nwod morf deilper ruhtrA
.taoc sih otni ti gnitekcop erofeb thgil gninrom eht ni revo ti gninrut
.eciov sih ni yrrow fo tnih a ,dias ybbat ehT
.ruhtrA ot kcab denrut eH
ytiradilos fo wohs
”,elbatrofmoc erom eb thgim taht edisni staes era erehT !taerg s’tahT“
,tnasaelp dna ynnus saw
.tfahs eht ffo elzzum sih dellup samohT ,kcab llup gnol a htiW
.supmac no noitnevnoc cimoc edirp lacol eht edistuo detiaw eh sa klawedis eht no doots ffitsam ehT  —
no kcab einaeb eht tup eh sa deilper tac eht
.eno taht evah nac uoY“
.yawa mih del dna wap sih koot tac eht erofeb
”,esoom a si ekaJ .ffeJ saw taht ,oN“  .deksa ruhtrA
.ylevitisiuqni dekool ffitsam ehT  ”!ffuts tinK“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
taht einaeb wobniar eht gniraew saw eH
,erom ecno ecalp ni detfihs eH
”.RDL na tnaw t'ndid ew dediced ew dna nwot evael ot dah ffeJ“
.ffitsam eht deksa reed ehT ”?thgir ,samohT
,surohc tnahpmuirt a ,tnemom elgnis a
”.tih a eb ll'ti teb I .yrB ,sknahT
,yliksuh dias ruhtrA ”,yob dooG“
.gnirednap eht lla dnim t'nod I ,yltsenoH“
.htolc nworb krad eht ot roloc emos gnidda
.seotamot gnilles llats a tsap deklaw yeht sa dias ffitsam eht
.elims mraw a samohT gnivig
.yldeticxe dias reed ehT
.ylireehc derewsna tac eht
.selbat dna gniroolf nedoow eht mraw ot swodniw ssalg ediw hguorht enohs thgilnus sa
?gniwohs seivom doog yna ereht erA“
”!ylrae siht tuo gnilles si tekram yadrutaS eht yaw on
.kcab daorb s’ffitsam eht dniheb noisivelet eht fo thgil eht ni yltneg gnibborht ,mucerp dna
.dehgual owt eht dna
.yawyna epytotorp a tsuj s'tI
.erom ecno elzzum mraw sih denepo eh sa ,deerga moT
”.uoy rof ydaer eno rehtona evah ll'I dna keew txen yb porD“
.kcab gnivaw ,dias reed ehT
”-enif s’ti dias I“  ”.oot
.elzzum sih htiw rebmem s’tac eht delzzun eh sa devom daeh egral
saw sihT     ”!gniog teg s’teL“
.dennirg nayrB ”!uoy stius tI“
.seye sih gnibbur ,moordeb eht fo tuo delbboh ruhtrA
.yldimit dias ffitsam ehT ”,sey ,mu ,hO“
,deilper samohT ”!tros eht fo gnihton ,oN“
.ylevil dna ecin saw ecnartne eht ta eltsub dna eltsuh eht dna
,retnuoc eht dniheb raeb a ot ylippah derettihc eH
detpurretni erew sthguoht siH
”.ereh ffuts fo tol a toG“
.detseggus terref ehT
.wap sih tuo dleh eH
.nirg gnirussaer a htiw deilper samoT
,ysub ylriaf saw efac ehT
s’ffitsam eht ta nwod deppolp eh ,hcneb eht gnidnuoR
,wap sih ni hctap llams eht ta derats eH
,seiceps dna ,redneg ,ytiliba ,epahs yreve fo sdneirf
”?gnihtyna htiw elbatrofmocnu uoy gnikam
.skcud deffuts ot sevolg dna sevracs morf gnignar ,skcank-kcink dna raew tink fo sdnik tnereffid htiw dellif saw llats ehT
”?gnol tiaw uoy diD“
”!uoy ees ot ecin ,haeY“
.esolc mih dellup dna redluohs
?mmH“  .swap sih ni eeffoc deci fo ssalg a dleh eh sa ediw seye sih
,tfahs s’tac eht ot wap eno thguorb eH
.ecidrawoc sih rof ta regnif sih tniop dluoc eh nomed A
.tekram eht detaroced taht srennab wef a ta gnikool ,deilper samohT
,oggodneP yb ”erutseG llamS A“
.tac ybbat eht ta nwod decnalg moT
:ot tnemetats lamrof a morf gnihtyna gnikaM
,ylleb tfos sih fo evruc eht revo pu dellup saw retaews siH
”!neht pu gnihtemos tes s'teL“
,seye sih desolc eh ,nwo sih otni wap s’tac eht gnikaT
”?noc cimoc edirp eht dnetta ot ereh uoy erA“
.ecruos eht ot gniog erofeb daeh kcils ,htooms eht revo dekcil eH
.elbatrofmocnu tlef eh yhw
,elzzum sih no daeh knip eht deppat samohT
.yaw emos ni tuo emoc ot gnivah sevlesruo dnif yam ew
,noitacinummoc htiw trofmoc lanosrep gnicnalab fo
sllats dna sfoor htolc eht revo wolley tfos a tsac nus ehT
”,sknaht oN !enif s'ti ,hO“
,mih no denael eh sa thgiew s’rentrap sih tlef eH
.no ti gnittup dna ffitsam eht morf kcab einaeb eht gnikat ,deilper ruhtrA
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
tra sih dna ytiniffaruf no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.evol ew esoht rof troppus dna
”,etsat ruoy tsurt t'nod I“
.ykseulb ro rettiwt no
”,sevitisop sti sah eno yrrebwarts eht kniht I“
,seldoon deirf ,eeffoc deci htiw edis yb edis degnarra
.sehctap llams fo elip eht ta dekool samoT
”?siht fo lla s’tahW ?uoy tuoba tahw dnA“ .kcab eht no reed eht gnittap
,kcohs kcom htiw dias ruhtrA ”,hctib uoY“
”.enoemos rof gnitiaw tsuj m’I“
.segassem rof ti gnikcehc
.samohT drawot dekool dna
,mulunerf dekcils-erp eht ta deppal eH
”!uoy no ecin skool ti kniht I ,haN“
.hcneb ybraen eht ta tiaw ot yawa kcab gniklaw erofeb ,delims moT .dnuora
”.neht ti ekat tsuJ“
.daeh sih fo pot eht no detser nihc a dna sredluohs sih dnuora depparw smra owt sa detpurretni erew sthguoht siH  ”…erutseg llams a“
,deilper moT ”,pleh ot yppaH“
.neewteb yal taht strap eht ot ssecca lluf evig ot
,ylleb sih no detser rehtona elihw hgiht sih tsniaga dehsup wap egral A
.evitanretla eht naht retteb llits s'tI
ot sa yromem cificeps a dah eh dehsiw eh ,semitemoS
erofeb daeh eht revo kcab taerter nikserof eht tel eh ,tfahs eht pu kcab eson sih gniliarT
”.doog gnileef ton er’uoy fi emoh og nac eW“
.deilper samohT ”,hguoht ekacnap eht htiw retteb skrow ssenimaerc s’naeb der ehT“
.ecnartne eht ta srennab deroloc ylthgirb eht dna tneve eht ta kcab dekool eh ,gnihgiS
,mih eciton dluow enoyna fi gnirednow saw mih fo trap A
?oS“ .deilper nayrB
”.eno ekat ll’I ,yllautcA .oN“
”!ot deen t'nod uoy ononoN“
s’tac ybbuhc eht fo tuo dekael taht mucerp eht gnitsat
.kcab syad wef a tog eh
erew selbategev dna stiurf hserF
”,naem uoy ,srovalf weN“
,elzzum sih otni taem mraw eht fo erom llup ot nageb eh ,yllautnevE
.htaenrednu daeh knip eht fo pit eht laever ot nikserof eht nwod gnillup ylluferac
.mih ni pu llew tnemeticxe fo tib a gnileef ,hctap eht ta nwod dekool eH .ylyhs
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.sthguoht nwo sih tsuJ
.ereh thgiarts tnew neht dnA“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tnecs elbaromem dna railimaf s’rentrap sih ni koot dna pit eht ta eson sih desserp eH
.llats suoiruc a ta gnikool
”.flesruoy tub gnihtyna eb ot deen t’nod uoY“
,snosaer fo edutitlum a rof
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.samohT ta dekrims eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tuo thgil ydaerla saw ti wodniw eht edistuo hguoht
.thgit tac ybbat yffulf eht gnigguh ,demialcxe nayrB
”?hctap edirp a ekil uoy dluow lleW“
.rentrap sih ta kool dluoc eh os yawa kcid gnibborht eht gnihsup
,uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,nageb tac eht ”,woN“
.raey eht rof seirots htnoM edirP ruo sedulcnoc taht dnA
”.ekaJ gnirb ll'I !emitemos rehtegot rennid emos evah dluohs eW“
.yltneg daeh s’moT fo pot eht gnilzzun ,dias ruhtrA ”!etal m’I yrroS“
,ylevixelfer dias eh ”,enif m’I“
”,bal eht gnisolc dehsinif tsuJ“  ”?uoy koot tahW“
seye sih ,daeha tnew tac ehT
.taht tuoba yrrow ot nosaer on dah eh wenk eh hguoht
”!uoy dessim I ?lrig gniod uoy er’woH“
.tem seye rieht dna
—  .erehwesle derednaw dnim sih fo eceip a ,llitS
,deksa tac ybbat eht
,dias reed ehT ”.etuc er’uoY“
.tfel terref eht sa gnivaw
.ylireehc dias eH ”!emocleW“
.rentrap derit sih gniynapmocca
”,thgirlA“  ”.dalg m’I“
”,siht ekat tsael ta tub ,eniF“  ”.oN“
htiw einaeb deroloc wobniar a saw tI .daeh sih ffo tink eht dellup ruhtrA
I leef semitemos tsuj I“
.eunev eht deretne taht stsitra dna sreog-noc eht gnitros ,kcehc ni gnihtyreve tpek stnadnettA
”.duorp em ekam uoY“
.keew rep sedosipe owt tcepxe nac uoy hcihw gnirud
.mih htiw nwod gniwob sreltna yvaeh sih
.daeh sih no einaeb eht decalp ruhtrA sa wap sih gnivaw ,dias samohT
.deregnil llits thguoht eht teY
oggodneP yb ”erutseG llamS A“
.dnah sih htiw flesmih gninnaf ,nihc sih desiar eH .denialpxe nayrB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
,derettu ylkciuq ffitsam eht
,tfahs mraw ,kciht eht nwod decart eh ,elzzum sih gnirewoL
.deilper nayrB
”!nayrB uoy gniteem ecin saw tI“
.erom ecno sehctap eht ta dekool eH .gnisuap erofeb
.tekram dnekeew eht rof pu tes erew sllats fo hcnub a dna
.spac tink deroloc fo
t’nod I ekil leef I
.etalocohc toh fo puc a gniraperp ysub saw ohw
,eludehcs margorP gnidaeR remmuS ruo nigeb ew ,keew txen fo sA
”.retteb rovalf naeb der lausu eht referp I“
.gniyrrac neeb d’ehs teksab eht gnisiar ,dias ehS ”,thgirlA“
”,srodnev wen emos era ereht epoh I“
elohw eht otni tif
.hguoht ,eno evah ylno I taht skcuS“
”.sroloc galf raeb htiw eno ekam dluoc I rO“
”!wen saw dnats ikayat ehT“
.daeh eht no ruhtrA gnittap ,deilper ffitsam eht
.noiton eht ta denworf eH
.enohp sih gnikcehc
revol sih ta pu dekool eH
.daeh eht laever ot kcab niks eht llup dna
.der srae ,dias ruhtrA ”…moT“
.daeh eht no delkcus eh sa sdlof tfos eht otni eugnot sih dils eh ,ssik a doohnam s’tac eht fo pit eht gniviG
”!ti ekil uoy epoH“
ria eht dellif srumrum teiuq dna eeffoc fo tnecs ehT
”,gnimoc si htnom edirp ekil skooL“
.eivom eht gnirud reilrae gnisaet morf kcils ydaerla
.samoT drawot gniklaw erofeb tekcaj sih revo ti decalp dna gab redluohs sih pu dekcip ylizal eH
”?thgir ,raguoc eht s’eH ?ekaJ“
.ti fo tnorf ni elbat a no
tuo kcid ytsat taht fo erom teg ot dap taf sih otni gnisserp
”.klaw eht morf gnitser tsuJ
.thgir sih morf emac eciov a sa
deilper moT ”,sknahT“
.etapicitrap ot
”.ytiurf ylgnihserfer s'tI“
.dias ruhtrA ”!hctap eciN“
”?taht yas uoy d’yhW“  ”.gniht yag
,yltfos dias samohT ”,melborp oN“
”.tol a snaem ti tub ,erutseg llams a tsuj s'tI“
.sllats eht hguorht deklaw
.srae rof edis eht ta stils llams
.ecaps tneve eht otni gnikeep ,gnidliub eht fo ecnartne eht drawot deklaw eH
,deilper moT ”,gnol oot toN“
.sehctap wobniar dehctits fo hcnub a htiw dellif saw tI
dna neercs sti morf thgil gnihsalf stohsnug
.llew sa elzzum sih no elims a
.deilper ffitsam eht ”…haeY“
.supmac eht raen retnec nwot llams eht hguorht deklaw owt eht sa
.rood eht denepo eh sa dias samohT
neeb I evaH“ .srae eht neewteb ffitsam eht tep ot sgel sih neewteb gnihcaer
.ssik kciuq a mih evag dna ezag sih tem ffitsam eht dna ,pu dekool ruhtrA
s’ffitsam ehT   .tsehc sih no wap s’tac ybbat eht otno dloh ot
,deyartrop netfo sa
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.elggig nayrB gnikam
eno siht piks esaelp
.no seohs sih tup eh sa yawllah eht hguorht tuo dellac samohT ”!tsafkaerb rof kcip doog a teg t’now ew etal oot er’ew fi ,yeH“  —  ”.trA ,uoy evol I“
?etunim a em evig uoy naC
,deffins dna sllab lluf eht otni delzzun eH
loord htiw denetsilg kcid dezis-yltsedom s’tac ehT
retaews sih htaenrednu deppils rehto eht elihw
hcamots hsulp eht revo dna pu dehcaer ylwols wap emas ehT
”.yltnecer lles ot yllacificeps sgniht gnikam neeb evah ew hguohT“
”,ereh gnitiaw htiw enif m’I“
.tnemeuoned latnedicninu erem si lla hcihw retfa xamilc citamard a
.kniw ykeehc a god gib eht gnivig ,dekrims eH
.sdrac samohT dna ruhtrA gnidnah ,dias reed eht
,sniatruc eht hguorht thgil mid tsac nus tes ylraen ehT —   ”?eerf uoY
,dewehc eh sa ylthgils denworf ffitsam nworb ,yklub ehT
.ffitsam yksuh eht ta decnalg eH
.nirg gnirussaer a rentrap sih gnivig ,deilper ffitsam ehT ”!thgirla m'I ,oN“
deklaw yeht sa sgalf edirp suoirav eht gnitneserper snip dna ,stelecarb ,strihs tnereffid erow ynaM
.spil sih ta pit eht gnicalp
”!etuc s'tI“  ”?thgir ytterP
”.netfo erom bal eht fo tuo teg ot deen I .niaga gnitarbelec eb annog s’ytisrevinu ehT“
,dehgual tac eht ”,haeY“
,deilper ruhtrA ”,dlo emas ,dlo emaS“
.setalp dna spuc desu pu gnikcip
.noitnetta ot kcab gnippans ylwols dnim deldda-erusaelp sih ,deksa ruhtrA
.nwod dna pu debbob eh sa tfahs eht fo erom gnikat
,deksa ybbat yerg ,ybbuhc A
”.htnom edirp rof erom gnikam no nalp eW
.enon dah eh teY
llits saw ria gninrom etal ehT
,gab regnessem s’moT fo palf eht no decalp saw hctap wobniar llams A
.sdlrow ysatnaf dna syug gib sevol ohw retirw lausac dna tsitra na
,eeffoc sih fo pis a koot eH .remrif ylthgils tey ,s’tac ybbat eht naht
emac ohw stseug dna ,ytlucaf ,stneduts htiw dellif saw edisni ehT
,yad yreve ,yad ynA