.eb reve ll’I sa ydaer sa m’I snaem tahT
,ycavirp eht emoclew d’I
”.ffuts dna setalp barg dna esav a ni srewolf eht tup og ll’I dna elbat eeffoc eht no doof eht tuo yal uoy t’nod yhw ,thgir llA
– doof reh ta selbbin inaD sa edis eht ot ecnalg kciuq a laets ot neercs eht morf yawa seye ym yrp I
.evael ot euc ym s’taht ezilaer I
.desrever si noitisop ym erehw eno ni paws dna
.kcehc – nekat noitacideM   2 fo
.secneirepxe +TBGL
.em dnuora reh dna
,hgis yvaeh a tuo gnitteL   .siht od nac uoY
,yltfos seilper ehs ”,wonk I“
.ysatnaf ym ni reh otni spih ym kcub ot nigeb dna efil laer ni hteet ym hcnelc I   .gnorw
”.ecaJ ,yaD s’enitnelaV yppaH“
.ecalp ni em gnizeerf ,sniev ym ni eci ot snrut doolb yM
.ytpme pu emoc I tub ,noitacidni yna rof niarb ym hcraes yllacitnarf I
…neht dna ,sreh otni sserp dluow ydob ym
”?tog ev’uoy tseb eht yllaer taht sI“
.regnorts sworg doof esenihC eht fo amora eht sa elbmur ot gnitrats hcamots ym leef nac I
.nwod og ot gniunitnoc morf ti peek ot od nac I gnihton s’ereht tub
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.nigeb ot erehw wonk neve t’nod I
.sniamer meti eno ylno litnu
htiw tcatnoc latnedicni ym morf denaelg ev’I tahw
ev’I – pmal daehrevo eht htaeneb elbisiv ylthgils llits era skeehc derruf-ynwat esiwrehto reh no selkceps etihw ehT
.ylpmil edis ym ot pord ti tel I
.esahcrup rof elbaliava won si
,thgilpmal nedlog eht ni sdlareme ekil gnitallitnics seye neerg esoht
.nials eb ot nomed a ekil sleef ti ,thginoT
.moor eht ssorca morf em ta skool ehs yaw ehT
,kcen reh ni ecaf ym yrub I ,reh revo gninaeL
dne no sdnats ydob ym no ruf fo dnarts yrevE
,efahc ot nigeb niks evitisnes eht leef I taht
.reh ta nwod maeb I sa em dniheb sgaw liat yM   ”.ecaJ
.ytilauxesa sih htiw
”,inaD ,yag ton m’I“
?tuo ti erugif t’nac I neve fi em fo edisni no gniog s’tahw dnatsrednu reh ekam ylbissop I dluoc woH
nehctik eht ot revo hsad-flah I .emarfrood eht no sesor eht pmub ot ton luferac
.etal oot s’ti tuB
”.em ekil yug a htiw tuo og dluow uoy sa lufituaeb sa enoemos yaw on s’ereht tub ,dneirflrig ym htiw etad a rof ereh m’I
– llihc os era stnerap reh dalg m’I
.hctiws ot emiT .won demirp m’I tuB
.tnemom gnol ylgnizinoga na rof sesuap ehS
,liated gnitaicurcxe ni sdneirflrig rieht htiw gniod ebircsed sdneirf ym tahW .’lamron‘
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.emahs dna yteixna dna noitartsurf dna tbuod fo gof a ni ylsselmia gnirednaw ,erehwesle si dnim yM
yaw a sdnif ecaJ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.sraet htiw gninetsilg won era skeehc reh taht eciton I dna ,sreviuq pil reH   .rettups I
.eergasid ro eerga ot elbanu
ffrhw tfos a tuo tel reh raeh I
.kcehc – dekcol rooD   .kcehc – desolc rooD
.ylbidua splug ehS
dna srexob ym fo dnabtsiaw eht nwod llup I ,rehto eht htiW
– kcen ym dnuora depool smra reh
’.tnemirepxe‘ siht trats neve ot hguone gnol tsal t’now I ,etar siht tA
reh fo edisni gnixamilc flesym erutcip ot yrt I
.liaw ot gnitrats ,smialcxe ehs
,ylwols gnivom s’ti won tub
.ysatnaf ym t’nsi sihT .oN   …neht dnA
?seirots ynam os htiw ti daol yhW
– tuo striuqs erp eroM   …ot gniraperp
.emit driht a rof daeh ym ekahs I ,drah gniwollawS
– eman ym gnillac ,gninaom ,gnihctiwt
I…sdrow htiw doog yllaer ton m’I“ .hsulf I
,dekan si ydob mils reh ,semit esoht ekilnU
– yltsenoh ,teews fo dnik saw tI
.pal reh otni llaf ti gnittel
.tnetnoc dna raluger
”.inaD ,yaD s’enitnelaV yppaH“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rood eht ot teg ot reh rof sekat ti sdnoces wef eht tiaw I sa rettulfa traeh ym dna htaerb detab htiw tiaw I
.dnuorgkcab eht ni gninord esion erem cisum eht
I taht taerg os si
,pets-dim esuap em gnikam
.eivom eht gnihctaw ot kcab og su fo htoB
.reh ssarrabme ot mees yeht sa hcum sa ,meht devol syawla
.tsap eht ni semit sseltnuoc ffo em nettog evah taht serutcip fo stes lareves htiw eno
– tsurht hcae htiw msagro gnihcaorppa ylidaets reh gninigamI
.ni em sezzub ehs sa skcolnu gnidliub tnemtrapa s’inaD ot rood ssalg ehT   .kcilc…tzzB
.gniwolg dna gnitnap htob er’ew ,retal stnemom wef a ffo ti kaerb ew nehW
.reirc a fo hcum ton m’I
,tuo deyalps si inaD dneirflrig ym ,em woleB
.nepo ti hsup I sa em steerg dnoyeb reyof eht fo gnithgil tnecseroulf hsrah ehT
.em hguorht tnemeticxe fo evaw a dnes elims yoc dna seye tnadrev reh ,ti snepo ehs nehW
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.ylesret pans I
.hgiht ym tsniaga gnidils dnah s’inaD leef ylneddus I nehw niaga ecno gnippils flesym dnif I
.elppin reh revo regnif ym ecart ylthgil
iloccorb htiw feeb dna niem ol fo etalp a nwod gnifracs em
.yltnecer eciton ot ton dedneterp ev’I
,em fo edisni gnitcarter era sllab ym hguoht sa sleef ti ,em gnitalumits morf raF
.deb ot enog ecnis gnol evah stnerap ym dna thgindim s’ti tub ,maercs ot tnaw I
– esnetni seye reh ,thgit si ecaf reH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.em otni kcab reh hcra
skeehc ym nwod gniwolf morf sraet eht pots t’nac I tuB
?siht ekil leef ti seod yhw oS
deredisnoc eb dluow tahw fo egnar eht edistuo raf ,raf sllaf mih htiw gniod s’ehs tahw tub ,no denrut ylraelc meht fo htob
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
tsirw reh no wap ym yal dna flesym fo dloh a teg yllanif I
,elzzum ym morf yawa sehcni erem snetsilg avluv reH
”tsdiM ruO ni neilA nA“
ro stnaw ehs sa reh eporg ot deifitrom ooT
.ylpeed reh evol I
.taht ot dnopser ot elggurts I sa
– troffe hctid-tsal a ekam I ,etarepseD
”tsdiM ruO ni neilA nA“
.siht ekil gnihton
”?gniht suoigiler driew fo dnik emos ti sI“
,enim htaenrednu morf tuo dnah reh pils inaD eciton I ,ssensuoicsnoc ym fo yrehpirep eht nO
.slirtson s’fles detcejorp ym sesuffus fo kniht nac I tnecs tnasaelp tsom eht dna
.sey yas ot seldoon fo lluf oot htuom ym ,don I
taht wonk I ,tnatsni na nI
.tsehc reh tsniaga pu desserp si wap ym litnu reh sdrawot ti sllup ehs ,reh pots nac I erofeB
.yawllah eht nwod knils dna yawa flesym llup I
.egacbir ym fo tuo tsrub thgim traeh ym leef I taht tniop eht ot snekciuq eslup yM
.tnuocca yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,gniliec eht ta pu kool ot tnemom a ekat I
,levon ecnamor yag htgnel-lluf a dehsilbup yltnecer sah eH
.rac ym otni yaw ym ekam dna
.worromot hguorht tsal nac I tbuod I taht
.redrah pmup ot trats I ,cinap fo egniwt railimaf-oot-lla na gnileeF   !tihs ,tihs ,tihS
.reh ta pu kool ot daeh ym tlit dna afos eht morf seye ym leep I ,yltnatculeR   ”.klat ot deen eW“
:reh ot em sward reh tuoba gnihtyrevE
,riahc ym otni pmuls dna tuhs potpal ym fo dil eht mals I
.tsaerb reh puc ot nwod edils ylwols ot wap ym wolla dna
.yrrac ot gnilggurts m’I smeti suoirav eht revo skool ehS
.rood tnorf reh fo bonk eht gnitsiwt dna
,enim no spil reh fo etsat eht ,ecarbme eht fo ssenthgit eht yojne I
,em gnillik si noitapicitna ehT
.gninetfos noitcere ym leef I ,ytilaer ni kcaB
,sksa ehs nehw flesym rof deredro I seertne owt eht hguorht yaw eht fo retrauq a tuoba m’I
– tuoekat esenihC fo gab eht dna
.ta dekool eb ot ylno gnihtemos
,em ta nwod gnirats
su neewteb sllaf ecnelis drawkwa nA   ”’.toh‘ toN“
.worromot ti tuoba gnitaolg eb dna tnatsni na ni em htiw secalp hctiws dluow sdneirf ym fo llA
,lakcaj elam a gnilddarts si erah elamef A
ebyam…reh eldnof ,reh ezeeuqs ot em stnaw ehs wonk I ,won thgiR
.setunim ylno ekil leef taht sruoh rof gnihtyna tsomla tuoba klat nac ew yaw ehT
.yaw emas eht sdne ti
,ylteiuq yas I ,regnol yna ti ekat t’nac I nehW
.taht ekil gnihtyna sevlovni seisatnaf lufwa ,errazib ym fo yna ni gnihtoN
dna wols gnihtaerb reh
.lamron yletomer gnihtyna ni tseretni ekat ot ydob ym ta gnimaercs m’I sa hcum sa
,reh sdrawot gninrut flesym erutcip I
.tseb ym od I tub
.daeh ym ekahs I ,niagA
?ecalp thgir eht yllaer siht sI“
dna yrc a tuo tel ot reh gnixaoc
,psarg ym fo tuo sedils dna elims-flah elttil a em sevig ehS
”.dluow reven uoy wonk I esuaceB
.rovaf ym ot skrow taht tub ,revo yats em tel d’yeht taht llihc os ton ylbaborp er’yehT
”.os kniht t’nod I ,oN“
.em epacse ot eunitnoc sdroW
dna smsaps ylneddus kcoc ym naht eno no dekcilc I dah renoos oN
.ot em stnaw neve ylbaborp ehS
,evah t’ndluohs yllaer uoY
yltnetsisni os rebmem ym nwod dna pu gnibbur dna gnizeeuqs m’I
.hctorc ym sdrawot yllufesoprup
– nepo gniws ot ti teg ot woble na htiw nottub elbissecca-riahcleehw eht sserp I ,tnurg a htiW
.moor tilnoom ,mid a ni gninetsilg
thgin raelc ,dloc eht otni tuo egdurt ot flesym ecrof I neht tub
,regnif elgnis a htiw elppin reh dnuora elcric I ,elppus dna tfoS
,hcuoc eht no dexif niamer I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,spih reh no swap ym
.htgnel ym revo kcils naht rehtar ykcits leef ot nigeb wap ym fo sdap eht
,spil reh gnikcil
.draeh eb yam dna ,nekops eb yam nettogrof dna dlotnu tfel esiwrehto seirots taht si
.noitisop s’lakcaj eht ni flesym enigami dna seye ym esolc I
,gnikael regnol on s’ti taht won dna
– elbarusaelp erom yletinifni
,ffo flesym gnikorts
ylesnetni os sleef ti tey dnA
”.erehwemos nwod meht tup dluoc I fi ecin eb dluow ti tuB !ot yppaH“
.eussi eht neeb reven s’tahT
,reh ot detcartta leef nac I taht yaw elbissop yreve nI
,gnidaelp ,txen emoc wonk I sdrow eht yas nac ehs erofeb ffo reh tuc I
.wap ym ni eno puc dna revo hcaer ylisae os dluoc I
.em rof reisae ti ekam ot smra reh esiar yllufpleh d’ehs
.strams reh ,romuh reh ,skool reh
,ereht ti gnicalp reh rebmemer t’nod I
.ecaJ ,uoy evol I“
?hguoht ,pu reh gnileeF
.em tnaw ot uoy tnaw I“
,syas neht ,taorht reh sraelc ehS
.revo evird ot rac eht ni deppoh I ecnis gnirednop neeb ev’I enil pukcip eht yrt I
.yretsym on si rewsna ehT
,retaes-owt ’stnerap reh no edis yb edis gnittis er’ew retal setuniM
.tnasaelpnu s’ti taht si llet yllaer nac I lla tub ,noisuf zzaj-cinortcele emos ekil sdnuos yleugav tI
.ekop a hcamots talf ym gnivig erofeb ton tub
.etad s’enitnelaV nwo rieht no tuo tnew yeht elihw enola su fo owt eht tfel evah dluow enim yaw on s’ereht
.inaD ot detcartta m’I
won shtnom xis rof gnitad neeb ev’ew tuB
– noitautis siht ni od ot desoppus m’I tahw noisivne nac I
,sgnidaer eseht fo ,gnirehtag siht fo esoprup ehT
,tsam lluf ot teg ot em sekat ti sdnoces eht nI
,seveels eht hguorht smra ym gnidils
,elahxe ytrons a tuo gnittel ,tey dnA
esrevrep dna egnarts os stnetnoc htiw setisbew devas fo
,erutseg yrotailicnoc a ni swap reh sesiar ehS
.dloh sekat noisicedni neht tuB   ”!oN“
,reh ssik ot ni nael d’I
”.nosaJ ,uoy dnatsrednu t’nac tsuj I .wonk t’nod I“
.hcum os inaD evol I
.em morf yawa flesreh sllup yllanif ehs litnu tsehc reh tsniaga pu desserp sniamer ti
.ylerumed daeh reh tsniaga kcab desserp srae reh
.hguoc drawkwa na tuo tel yllanif I erofeb
.ttum ,yrgnuh syawla er’uoY“ ,sesaet ehs ,eugnot reh gnikcilC
,setalocohc fo xob depahs-traeh eht ,sesor fo teuquob eht neewteb swap eerf on evah I
yadot semit modnar ylgnimees ta esnetni os emoceb dah ’deen‘ ehT
.em ot gnisuora ylbabircsedni tey egnarts ylesnetni gnihtemos od ot tuoba
.llew oot tib a dekrow evah yam sutaih yM   .tey toN .oN
taht seye reh ni regnuh a htiw em ta pu gnirats
.ekawa flesym peek ot daeh ym ekahs ot evah I semit wef A
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.enim tsniaga deltsen si ydob reh nehw leef I htmraw ehT
yllaretil ,neercs no rehto hcae dnuora elcric sdael owt eht hctaw ot eunitnoc ylpmis I ,elihw a roF   .guh-edis a ni resolc reh gniggut ,tsiaw reh ta tser ot emoc wap ym dna reh dniheb dnuora
,ylper ylkciuq I ,reh ta gnikwaG
– eb ot tnecs eninimef reh enigami I tahw fo elahni peed a gnikat
.gnihctaw ot kcab og dna snoihsuc hcuoc eht otni knis flesym tel dna xaler I
,ni sregnif owt edils ylluferac ,yltneg I
.resolc dna resolc dnah reh gnihcni no speek dna em gnizies cinap eht eciton ot mees t’nseod inaD
,arb reh psalcnu ot kcab reh dniheb hcaer d’ehS
.tuo meht llup neht ,em
?yag yllautca I mA
– sredlof skramkoob detsen fo seires a hguorht dapkcart eht etagivan yllacinahcem I ,wap eno htiW
.em ta worbeye na sesiar dna pih reh no dnah a secalp ehS
.inaD htiw deb ni thgin elohw a dneps ot dah I fi od d’I tahw wonk t’nod I…tub
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR   .dlot eb
,ylevitarugif dna
.em ta worbeye na gnisiar ,sretnuoc ehs ”?erus uoy erA“
tub wap ym esu I nehw ekil s’tI
”.su neewteb eb reve ll’ti lla si siht fi
.siht deirt ev’I semit rehto eht fo lla ekil tsuj pu evig I ,htaehs ym otni tcarter ot seunitnoc rebmem ym sA
”.wonk I tub ,ti dnatsrednu t’nod I“
,es rep ,gnirob si eivom eht taht ton s’tI
,hguoht ,elbat eeffoc eht no ssem eht yawa raelc ot strats dna hcuoc eht morf pu steg ehs nehW
,ni em tel ot kcab spets ehs sa reh tsap eldis I ,gniggaw llitS
– sdloh selegnA soL esimorp eht tuoba gnignis
.yhs tsuj erew uoy thguoht I ,tsrif tA“
.drawrof dexif seye reh htiw yleneres gnilims s’ehs
,snruter ehs nehw hcuoc eht no pu slruc ehS
eht…ereht morf og dluow sgniht erehw gninigami dnA
.emit emas eht tuoba ta gnitae hsinif eW
.enob eht ot em stuc em tsniaga sneffits ehs yaw ehT
.hgis tfos a htiw redluohs ym no daeh reh gnitser
.flesruoy rof tuo ti tros ot emit emos uoy evig ll’I“
,siht ekil gniog peek t’nac I tuB
”tsdiM ruO ni neilA nA“
,tnaw I sa kcab wap ym ward
.yhsup os syawla erew sdneirfyob rehto ym
”.enim fo etirovaf a s’tI
.su neewteb revo s’ti
sekorts nep etarebiled htiw eno hcae hguorht gnikirts flesym enigami dna
”.yag ton er’uoy ,KO ,KO“
.ereht thgir era stsaerb reH
.rehtie ,noitnetta ym peek ot hcum gniod ton s’ti tub
:gniht eno rof tpecxe…gnihtyrevE
.sraet reh hguorht gnilims
,god.ecioveht ta
,roloc fo sbolb gnitfihs era neercs no dnuora gnivom elpoep eht
snoitasnes eht morf detaicossid m’I – neila s’tI
.wap ym otno selbbird erp fo tib a
.gnissik htiw delggurts reven ev’I
.ylpeed erom reh ssik dna enim otni ydob llams reh llup I
.tsehc thgils reh fo gnillaf dna gnisir wollof I
.VT no ro seivom ni detciped nees reve ev’I elam dedoolb-toh rehto yreve ro sdneirf ym ekil ton m’I ,nosaer pu dekcuf revetahw roF
dnim ym morf ysatnaf oobat eht epiw I ,lennahc a gnippilf m’I hguoht sA
,srrup ehs ,elzzun a em evig ot ni gninaeL
,enoz neddibrof a ekil s’taht em oT
otni eb ot smees esle enoyreve tahw dna em ot ’toh‘ s’tahw neewteb pag eht ,niagA
.rehto hcae ssik naht erom gnihtyna enod t’nevah ew dna
sredlof neddih ,terces
,oot ,dloheb ot thgis tnasaelp a eb dluow ydob dekan reh wonk I
eno siht piks esaelp
.rebmem tcere-flah ym revo eporg yldi ot nigeb
.em eveileb t’nseod ehs kniht em sekam enot reh ni gnihtemos tub
– ”…taht si fo kniht nac I gniht rehto ylno ehT
.ti nialpxe ot tpmetta neve ot woh wonk t’nod
”-t’nod uoy fi ,tuB
slautir ylthgin fo tsilkcehc latnem ym ezilausiv I ,gniliec knalb eht ta pu gniratS
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,xoF yT yb
.esnes citehtsea na ni ylno fi
.egde no em stes tsuj thguoht
?htnom edirp fo tuo laed a gib os
.ti dnuora psarg ylmraw neht
,si taht – slrig htiw xes gnivah tuoba thguoht ev’I sa hcum sa syug htiw xes gnivah tuoba thguoht ev’I
dna srac no dnuora gnicnarp elpoep – bmud os s’tI
teef ym ot teg ylwols I ,sessalom ekil gnileef sgeL
.reh htiw rehtegot gnieb sa yppah sa em sekam gnihtoN
,od I tahw rettam oN
.ti ni dneirflrig efil-laer ym enigami ot lufemahs dna egnarts oot s’ti ,si erutcip taht sa toh sa dna
”.oot uoy evol I ,inaD ,esaelP“
.ni ti edils dna kcoc demirp ym revo muc reh bur I
,yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I
dehcaer sah sseninroh ym ,gnitabrutsam morf nekat ev’I kaerb yad-eerht eht nI
…erusaelp etamitlu eht
,sthgil eht mid ot pu steg ehS
,ekil sllems ti tahw wonk ylurt ot em dnuora no denrut os neeb reven s’ehs
tsum taht seirots era eseht dnA
,fles yffurcs-oot ,niht-oot ym tsniaga pu deltsen ,ereh s’ehs dnA
.hpargotohp a naht rehtar gniredner citsitra na si erutcip ehT
”!?em hcuot uoy t’now yhw nehT“   ”-morp I ,toh era uoY .yrros m’I…I ,inaD“
.lla ta tsixe yeht gnikcohs s’ti taht
.nac I erofeb ti swardhtiw ehs tub
.tcefrep os ,etaciled os ,llams os si ydob reH
.liava on ot tub sucof ot yrt I
,ysatnaf neddibrof ym ni inaD rof erah eht tuo paws I
.od dluow VT no ro seivom ni detciped nees reve ev’I elam dedoolb-toh rehto yreve ro sdneirf ym tahw ,tsael ta
,taoc ym gnibbarg fo snoitom eht hguorht og yllacinahcem I
– daeh reh revo dna pu ti edils ot trats dna retaews gnittif-esool reh fo meh eht barg d’I ,tnurg tfos a htiW
.ressik doog yllaer a m’I em sllet netfo ehs taht truh t’nseod tI
?raf oot gniog ro em gnitruh fo diarfa uoy erA“ .daeh ym ekahs I
.tsaf laer dlo tog emit eht lla em fo ffo meht gniyrP
”,lufituaeb er’uoY .tsenoh ,taht ton s’ti ,esimorp I ,inaD ,oN ?tahW“
,gniht ym t’nera yllaer slacisum ,dlot eb hturT
.laiceps gnihtemos eb thgim siht taht thguoht I
,em erofeb neercs eht no egami llits eht ta pu gnicnalg
?dnaL aL aL tuoba leef uoy od woh ,yeH“
”.uoy fo lla – uoy tnaw I
– regnol stnemom wef a rof ereht dnats eW
,nirg reilavac a si epoh I tahw htiW
.yug taerg a er’uoY
,elbat eht no nwod gnihtyreve tes ylluferac ot
.em fo retteb eht teg snoitome ym gnittel ton fo tniop a ekam ot yrt I
.eod suoegrog a s’ehs taht tbuod on s’erehT
,seye reh ni tnilg luftsul a ,erah ehT
.sgniriap lauxesoreteh devlovni seisatnaf citore ym fo lla ,taht naht eroM .reven
dnuora sehcnelc ehs sa taeh ydob reh gnileef
yojne esaelP  .daD regdaB yldduC
s’ti – nrop maertsniam
.dad regdab yldduc
?siht tnaw I t’nod yhW
:deksa neeb sah noitseuq eht taht tsetta nac eW
*	      *	      *   ?em htiw gnorw si kcuf eht tahW
,em dniheb nehctik eht ni gnilffins inaD fo dnuos eht hctac ot drawkcab skriuq rae yM
.tcartsba eht ni lufrednow meht dnif I hguoht neve
.taht ta yletaidemmi pu krep srae yM   ”?yag uoy erA…“
.ecaJ ,htaerb peed a ekaT
.em spots syawla edisni gnihtemos tuB
.reh htiw xes evah ot tnaw t’nod I
.moor gnivil eht ot kcab klaw neht
.sreh tsap pils ot eugnot ym wolla ot spil ym gnitrap dna edis eht ot elzzum ym gnitlit
pils mra ym tel I daetsni oS
.niorg ym hcaer ot tuoba s’ehs sa tsuj
.dniheb morf reh dnuora smra ym parw ot evom dna
.lla retfa ,reh rof si thginot – eugra ot gniog ton m’I tub
.srumrum ehs ”’,lufituaeB‘“
.evaw ladit a ekil em otni hsarc reilrae morf sraef ym lla ,hsalf a nI
,setis desu-llew erom ym fo eno no ediced I
”?dloc steg doof eht erofeb tae dluohs ew ebyaM“
.niaga reh ta revo ecnalg I
.ecaJ ,ti teg t’nod I nehT“
.dneirfyob reh morf sdeen ehs yaw eht ni ton…tsuJ
lworg wol a tuo tel I
1 traP ,xoF yT yb
.fo erus m’I hcum tahT
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.niaga drah em teg ot hguone ylerab tsuj spleh tI
.nees reve ev’I elims tseddas eht s’tI
.ecno tsael ta ti ees yllaer dluohs uoy ,slacisum ekil uoy fI
.VT eht no snoitpo gnimaerts eht hguorht gnippilf reh dna
.citnarf emoceb sekorts wap ym sa lasuora fo level siht ta em speek
,drow rehtona tuohtiW
ylleb dna tsehc erab reh fo ruf keels eht
.gnimlehwrevo era riapsed dna noitartsurf dna sserts eht tub ,esaeler taht sdeen llits em fo trap A .ylivaeh gnitnap
.spots dna tnih eht steg ehs feiler ym ot tub ,em tsniaga ydob reh tsujda dna
.ereht…em hcuot ot inaD tnaw t’nod I ?od I od tahW
.slevel neesnu ylsuoiverp
.em tsniaga stlem ehs sa tsehc ym ni htmraw eht
”.evitcartta m’I kniht t’nod uoy taht
.em no daolnu ot reh rof tiaw I sa ezag reh dloh yltnelis I os
leehw gnireets eht tsniaga daeherof ym sserp I sa
,ylgnirussaer dnah reh tep ot tuo hcaer si od ot kniht nac I llA
.amoc doof ot bmuccus ot snetaerht ydob ym sa dnim ym ni rehtegot rulb ot gnitrats senecs eht
”.retteb hcum s’taht ,eeS“
.siht fo sraey gnikcuF
?em rof lla esehT“
?thgir ,od ot yug a rof gniht lamron a yllatot s’taht tub ,ssorg ytterp gniggarb eht dnuof syawla ev’I ,detnarG
.niaga drah oot gnipmup m’I
.rehto hcae rof tnaem erew ew tahT
…“ – repsihw raen a ot gnippord eciov reh ,sllaf ecaf reh
.lufituaeb s’ehS .dneirflrig ym s’inaD
:dneirflrig rieht morf raeh ot sdaerd dneirfyob yreve sdrow ruof eht raeh I dna ffo skcilc VT eht nehw hcuoc reh fo noihsuc eht otni seloh gnirats m’I
.shgis dna tsehc reh ssorca smra reh sdlof ehS ”…won dnA
tsael yrev eht ta ro
.won yltnetsisni ssel tib a
,yrd ot nugeb sah erp ehT
,ydob ym esnet dna pil rewol ym etib I
.rebmun taebpu na htiw yletaidemmi tsomla ffo skcik eivom eht sa ni elttes eW
smret ot emoc ot
,ediserif eht ta ,ekam uoy od yhw
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.suoitcefni elttil a ygrene eht dnif tub pleh t’nac I tub
,gnitcartsid oot semoceb kcoc der-debbur ym morf sseneros ehT
dnuora deretnec seirots gnillet no sesucof ohw rohtua yrruf a ,xoF yT yb
,yaw taht ni em deticxe reve s’taht gnihtemos ton s’ti ebyaM
.em nihtiw deen a sllifluf llits ti tub
.kcab msagro gnimocno eht gnicrof
.esae yrotcnufrep htiw tuoba og
.kcehc – dehsurb hteeT
.VT eht fo edis rehtie no sesac yalpsid eht ni semarf erutcip dna skcank-kcink suoirav eht fo setteuohlis eht tuo ekam ot em rof hguone thgirb tsuj meht gnivael
.enecs eht ni daeha pmuj ot ediced I os ,tnemom eht gnisol m’I
.potpal nepo ym ot dnuora leviws dna riahc eciffo ym otni knis I
.ria citcra eht fo tuo teg ot nac I sa ylkciuq sa edisni pils neht
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
:secafruser noitseuq railimaf a tuB
.thgir eht ot tinu tsrif eht si sreH
,sruotnoc tfos rieht leef dna stsaerb erab reh no elttes swap ym sA
,ot drawrof kool I gnihtemos si siht yllamroN
.no seye dial reve ev’I eod suoegrog tsom eht si yllaer ehS
.spil eht no kcep a em evig ot ni snael ehs ,yldaorb erom gnilimS   ”.uoy evol tsuj
.tes teg ot gnol yrev su ekat t’nseod tI
– eromyna ti ssecorp t’nac I
.draob a sa ffits og I dna
,ooc I ,ecaf ym no nirg gib a htiw tsiaw s’dneirflrig ym dnuora mra na gnikooH
.nediw seye reH ”!hO“
dna neercs eht ta gnikool ot kcab og neht ,xaler ot emit ydob ym gnivig
”.esaelp ,ni no emoc ,yrros m’I“
.dennalp evah I tahw fo esuaceb tsuj ton dna
hcihw ,lluP lanoitativarG
.bos ot nigeb dna