.ilA deman aneyh dettops egral ylevitaler a
.ereht liated erom yna otni og ot gniog ton m’I ”.taht ekil ton…tsuJ
.yadot tuo dnif I epoh I
”?won gnileef uoy era woH
– no m’I htap eht no niamer I rehtiE
.ti steg eno oN .esnes yna ekam t’nseod tI .si
,gnidliub htam eht tixe I sA
.tnemom gnissap hcae htiw sesaercni gnidoberof fo esnes ehT
,scipot fo tsil yrdnual rieht hguorht gniog sehsinif ilA emit eht yB
.desufnoc…m’I ,tsenoh eb oT“
.em ta gnikniw meht leef I tub ,em ta kniw t’nod yehT
”.ni tif I fi wonk t’nod I“
.enips ym nwod snur llihc yci na sa redduhs I
.won ereh m’I ,ton ro gnoleb I rehtehW
,yldrawkwa dna ylrae dedne etad ehT
.lla rof dna ecno ecnailla eht htiw erutuf ym ediced thgim ti taht
”.doof hguone naht erom evah ll’eW
,drawrof spets ylbbow wef a ekat dna teef ym ot teg yllanif I nehW
– hguoht ,tuo pets nac ehs erofeB
,redluohs ym psarg ylmraw wap s’aneyh eht leef ylneddus I
.dnetta t’now I stneve dna
.niaga pu sepip ilA
,ffo ekahs elttil a ydob rieht evig yehT
.erofeb keew eht ekih eht ro ,keew tsal thgin aivirt eht ro ,kcultop eht ot gnimoc ot thguoht yna nevig t’ndah I hguoht sa ton s’ti ,llitS
.sessalc on fo syad artxe wef a ot drawrof kool nac I os ,snigeb kaerb retniw-dim won dna
,etarapes ew dna su dnuora gnivom elpoep fo elffuhs eht ni tsol si tnemom ehT
,ksa yllanif yeht
.wollaws drah a ekat I
.lley detaorht-lluf a ni tuo lla ti tel I dna
– lwoh lamirp ym fo tohsrae nihtiw elpoep era ereht fI
.srehto eht htiw gnihgual dna gniddon ,tneserp niamer I ,hguoht ,sthguoht ym otni ffo gnitfird naht rehtaR
.kcab eht no ylmrif em spalc neht
.redluohs eht no em pat wap reh leef I rood eht ot yaw eht no em sessap ehs sa tub
– eciov llams eht fo noitcerid eht ni pu spihw daeh yM
,taht retfa ytilamrof erem a neeb dah flesti pukaerb ehT
.trihs-T gnittif-esool a dna snaej gniraew
.dias ilA sa ,hguoht ,sgniteem eseht fo tniop eht yltcaxe t’nsaw tahT
.ssengnihton kcalb fo aes a ni tfirda ,ecaps retuo ni gnitaolf saw I taht eciton ot demees meht fo enoN
taht – moor ym morf yawa rehtraf gnitteg ylno m’I taht thguoht ehT
.seye rieht teem I sa elims yehT   .gnidnatsrednu
,tsehc ym fo tuo edolpxe ot gninetaerht traeh ym htiw tlah a ot decrof yllanif m’I nehW
”tsdiM ruO ni neilA nA“
2 traP ,xoF yT yb
,em ediseb trons ilA raeh I   ”…tihS“
,dworc eht hguorht gnitaolf ylbisivni neila na ton m’I taht
.moor eht dnuora srehto eht morf tnessa fo srumrum dima ni semihc ilA ”,thgir s’aeB“
,diasnu niamer lliw em llet ot detnaw ehs si ti revetahw taht gniwonk ,sknis traeh yM
seisatnaf citore sih taht tcaf eht htiw delggurts ecaJ ,emit tsaL
.roolf doowdrah eht gnola gniparcs swalc dna pu gnitteg elpoep fo sdnuos eht raeh I nehT
.moor eht fo retnec eht ni sriahc fo gnir eht nihtiw taes deipucconu na ekat I ,elbissop sa llams sa flesym ekam ot gniyrT
.leef I woh gnibircsed ot emoc s’enoyna sa esolc sa saw noitinifed s’aeB tub
.yadot yad yllihc fi lufituaeb a s'tI
.denedrubnu…os leef I
.reh retfa ni knils dna hgis peed a tuo tel I ,noitatiseh fo tnemom rehtona retfA
,yas yeht ,enola yletelpmoc tfel yllanif er’ew nehW
,yadot teews ylralucitrap s’tI
,rennid rof nepo sllah gninid eht litnu deb ni hsarc ot naht erom gnihton tnaw I ,yllaicepse yadoT
,dellepxe si aval eht fo lla litnu em fo tuo wolf snoitome ehT
.won ffo daeh ot evah I“
.ecaf eht ni em tlep dniw fo stsug nedal-wonS
”.puorg eht ot gnihtemos yas ot detnaw eh tub
.eno tnaw od srehto tub
– yldrawni nworf I
.swap ymmalc ym gnipsalcnu dna gnipsalc ylsuovren ,teef ym ot nwod ecnalg I
.snoitasrevnoc rieht elffum ot elttil seod rood eht tub
.em no ylno dexif era seye rieht fo lla woN   ”.sruoy si roolf ehT“
.dnuorgkcab eht otni edaf I dna
.won sraey evif no gniog rof delliflufnu enog d’taht esimorp a s’taht ,sdneirf ym fo eno ot gnidrocca tub
.tnaw uoy sa gnol sa rof sgniteem eseht gnidnetta peek nac uoy ,kooL“
.eulb dna ,elprup ,knip fo sdnab devaelretni eerht
.yadretsey em detivni yllanosrep dah ilA tnemom eht morf nwonk d’I tahw gnirucsbo neeb dah noitome fo sreyal ynam eht taht ezilaer I
.enif m’I .KO s’tahT
seednetta raluger eht fo eno htiw ecaf ot ecaf emoc I ,dnuora gnilrihW
.nwo ym htiw pu denil yltcaxe taht ecneirepxe devil rieht derahs evah dluow esle enoemos
– ereh gnieb eldnah ot elba eb ot gniog m’I yaw on s’erehT
.ti gniw llew sa thgiM
.reh ot kcab daeh ym pans ot em gnisuac ,yldetcepxenu syas ehs ”,retsemes tsal em ot deneppah ralimis gnihtemoS“
.tuoba ezisatnaf yllautca I tahw ebircsed nac I yaw on yletulosba s’ereht
meht neewteb tuo krow t’now
,yhsup ton tub yldneirf
– pit eht hguorht gnicreip rolocirt eht ot seye ym gniward
”.elihw a rof gnuts ti tub
.gnitseretni…ylralucitrap er’yeht enigami t’nac I ,tuB
”.ffuts…lanoitazinagro
.dnim ym morf raf neeb reven sah
.eb lliw reven I taht ssensselepoh eht dna dootsrednu gnieb reven fo hsiugna ehT .gnignol ehT
– nekops d’ew emit tsal ehT
.hguorht yawflah ragus doolb wol morf espalloc t’nod I erusne ot tuo yaw ym no rab nietorp a gnibbarg
.kcolc’o 8 ta dehsarc I taht
.thgim…ereh enoemos gnipoh saw I sseug I oS
– bos a kcab ekohc I   ”.t’ndluoc…I-I
,hU“   .ecalp tsrif eht ni ereh em thguorb dah taht nosaer elbapacseni emas eht rof tuo esle enoyna ro reh ksa erad reve dluow I taht ton
U“   .tsehc ym ffo yas ot ereh emac I tahw teg I sselnu – flesym yojne enola tel
.robhgien ym ot gnola dessap yletaidemmi d’I taht repap fo eceip elgnis eht pu dloh yehT
– etuc llits tub ,inaD morf tnereffid yrev
”?xes naht rehto sgniht ni detseretni ,wonk uoy
.secneirepxe
.retnec tneduts eht sdrawot htap niam eht ffo thgir a ekat I daetsni tub
,ereh yllaer m’I yhw tuoba pu nepo t’nac I fi ,puorg eht fo tser eht ot flesym ecudortni ot gniog ton m’I fI
O“ .terger htiw pu gnillews tsehc ym
,raey siht emitemos eno wen a no dnuorg kaerb ot gniog saw loohcs eht taht denoitnem dah remmus eht revo nettog d’I tekcap noitatneiro ehT
.ecaps otni ffo gnirats neeb ev’I taht ezilaer I dna
– detaler-loohcs gnihtemos ot stfird noitasrevnoc fo cipot eht
.reh stpurretni llebrood cinortcele s’ilA fo gniralb eht ,hguoht ,gnihtemos yas ot htuom reh snepo ehs nehW
,gnihtyreve erutpac yltcaxe t’ndid tI
.tcepxe t’nod I taht ereht ytilibarenluv a ees I ,seye nworb peed reh otni kool I sa – setatiseh ehS
”?guh a uoy evag I fi thgir lla eb ti dluoW“
semoc taht noitaneila eht fo ecneirepxe evah uoy rehtiE
.enigami ylecracs nac I ,ekil leef dluow taht tahW
.gnitnirps ylraen m’I erehw tniop eht ot snekciuq ecap yM
gnitlem eht morf hsuls htiw yddum won
.tseretni gningief si enoyna taht esnes eht teg t’nod I ,moor eht dnuora kool I sa tub
,reh htiw xes evah t’ndluow I ,llew ,esuaceb pu ekorb ew tub
.gnitaralihxe si ti sa railimafnu sa si gnignoleb fo esnes sihT
,smoor ruo ot kcab deklaw ew sa niarb ym ni dnuora elttar ot deunitnoc sdrow s’ilA
:era yeht taht gnileef eht epacse ot htuoy reeuq rof
.yaw taht ni reh tnaw t’nseod eh taht
.oga sraey fo elpuoc a ecnailla siht dnuof depleh yeht taht tpecxe meht tuoba elttil yrev wonk I
.ytilauxesa sih fo esuaceb
,wap ni sknird dna azzip ,meht dnif nac ew erehw staes nekat lla ev’ew retfA
,ereh gnimoc pots ot evloser ym niatniam
,dnekeew siht dnetta ot gniog er’yeht seitrap tarf eht rof tnemeticxe ylbbuB
.gnihtemos yas ot evah I wonk I
.keew yreve dleh si gniteem siht erehw moorssalc eht hcaorppa I sa emulov ni worg seciov railimaf yleugav ,lufreehc fo sdnuos ehT
– tsael ta ,yllanoitome dna yllatnem
.devirra doof eht ecnis nekops s’ehs emit tsrif eht – pu sepip ylneddus aeB ,sexob eht fo eno tuo llup ot pu steg ilA sa tub
,on – ffo liart I ”…lleW“
.drawrof gnillaf morf flesym peek ot swalc ym htiw esahcrup hguone dnif ot eganam tub
.gnahrevo s’gnidliub mrod eht rednu erutarepmet gnizeerf-raen eht ot etamilcca dna hcterts ot setunim wef a ekat I
.gnikniht s’ehs tahw wonk t’nod I taht elttil a em sllik ti ,ezag reh teem I emit hcae tub
.yllacitahpme don I
,syas dna wap ym sezeeuqs ilA ,ot flesym ecudortni ot elpoep erom on era ereht nehW
,krowten troppus a eb ot si puorg siht fo esoprup eht ,tsomerof dna tsriF
,sedis ym ot smra ym snip taht guh thgit a ni pu depparw flesym dnif yletaidemmi I
.taht naht detacilpmoc erom tol a si ytilauxesA“
.won trats ot meht tcepxe t’ndid I dna
.enoyna…otni m’I kniht t’nod I
.dessap emit sa tneuqerfni erom dna retrohs nworg dah snoitasrevnoc ruo dna
.pihsnoitaler a ni gnieb peek ot stnaw dna hcum yrev reh sevol eh taht tcaf eht etipsed
,esaelp ,su morf sdeen enoyna gnihtyna s’ereht fi oS
.tsael ta won rof ,der thgirb emas eht llits riah reh ,oot ereh si aeB
.meht ot eybdoog yas ot dnuora kcuts d’ohw srelggarts wef eht yb detpurretni er’yeht ,rewsna nac yeht erofeB
.gnimoc detrats I ecnis enoyna ot secnetnes owt dias ylerab ev’I
,smeti adnega suoirav rieht hguorht og ot setunim os ro ytriht tuoba sekat tI
,tfos si noisserpxe rieht
”?puorg eht oT ?gnihtemos yas I dluoC“
– daehrevo sthgil eborts fo sehsalf tnettimretni eht rednu cisum gnidnuop ot ecnad yeht sa sevlesmeht revo gnillaf elpoep fo aes eht fo taeh ydob evitcelloc eht morf gnikab ,yub nac yenom reeb tsepaehc eht gnigguhc ,sediseB
.tuo srebmem puorg rehto eht wollof ot nigeb dna
.msicitpeks eb ot ekat I tahw ni rae na gnisiar
.em ta pu smaeb ehs sa pu thgil ylneddus seye reH
.si ti tseuqer a egnarts woh redisnoc ot decrof m’I sa hsulf srae yM
,taht ta dne ot tuoba si noitasrevnoc eht taht esnes eht teg I
.ylwols yllufniap ssap hcihw
”.tnemtraped gnireenigne ,mre ,eht ni namhserf a m’I
.ranimes gnitirw namhserf reh ni yug a gniees saw ehs taht em no deppord ehs litnu rehto hcae ot ecnatsbus fo gnihtyna dias ylerab d’ew – s’raeY
– teg I esnes a tsuj si siht dna – tuB…“
.yletanutrofnu ,ti tuoba aedi gnorw eht evah elpoep fo tol A
.wonk yllaer t’nod won I tub
.ria looc fo tsug a ni gnittel ,rood eht snepo dna snrut ehs ,gniddoN
em nrecnoc t’nod taht slasoporp tuoba snoissucsid ot gninetsil morf deniag eb ot gnihton yllaer s’ereht neht
.ti tuoba gniklat erew yeht nehw yadirF no noitnetta gniyap neeb ylerab d’I
,nrut rieht sekat srebmem puorg rehto eht fo hcae ,eno yb enO
,yas yeht ,taorht rieht gniraelC
”.redneg etisoppo eht fo enoemos htiw pihsnoitaler a ni eb ot tnaw uoy taht snaem hcihw ,citnamororeteh gnieb sedulcni taht dna
.gnihton t’nsaw tI“
– ylthgils yteixna ym sekots tI
,yadnuS tuoba eil ym pu peek dluoc I
,si taht – citnamora osla era seca emoS
.nirg laineg a htiw gnir eht dnuora ecnalg yehT
,ereh eb d’ti ,dnatsrednu d’ohw enoyna dnif ot gniog saw I fi ,thguoht I
.reh rof yppah saw I taht reh dlot I nehw sraet kcab dloh ot dah d’I
.gninrom eht ni ruof ro eerht ta kcab reggats yeht litnu sdnuor eht gnikam sthgin yadrutaS dna yadirF rieht dneps ot eunitnoc dna ,seussi hcus on evah sdneirf ym esruoc fO   .ssennekorb …yM
,elahxe peed a htiw ydob ym evael
.emit elbatrofmocnu na eb ot sesimorp
.ti fo tsrow eht morf flesym dleihs ot
.efil ym ni tniop erutcnuj tnatropmi tsom eht ot resolc hcum taht em sgnirb petstoof yrevE
.yldeticxe kcilf ot strats liat trohs riehT
.htuom ym ni wap ym tup evah yllaer I wonk I emit sihT   ”.lamron…ton
.em hcaorppa ot tsal eht si aeB
”?emitemos eeffoc fo puc a teg ot tnaw uoy od…yeH“ ,remmats I
ereht saw ezilaer neve t’ndid I taht ydob ym ni noisnet a leef I
.detalosi leef em ekam ot gniht rehtona dedeen I fi sA
,enoyna dnif t’now I taht si em seifirret tahw ,oN
– lla ta erehwyna del ti fi
– enohp ym evah ot lufknaht os neeb reven ev’I
,semit fo tseb eht ta nosrep gniogtuo tsom eht ton m’I
.kaeps ot enoyna rof noitativni na htiw nepo ew ,lausu sA“
– yletaidemmi dnatsrednu ot smees ilA
.etairporppa si nuonorp eht fi gniksa er’yeht taht ezilaer ot em rof dnoces a sekat tI .em ta pu kool dna tnemom a esuap yeht
,em ot yas ot dab gnihtyna sah ehs tcepxe I taht ton s’ti
siht tahw wonk t’nod I esuaceb ,od ot tahw wonk t’nod I won dnA
?puorg siht ot yllaicepse ,ton ro ’lamron‘ s’tahw yas ot I ma lleh eht ohW
– imed yllautca m’I taht ezilaer em edam ti dna
– srehto lareves morf noitaresimmoc fo srumrum ot mretdim suluclac tnecer a gnitnemal si samohT sa em ot decudortni namiac delcatceps a
,inaD ,dneirflrig sih htiw etamitni gnieb evlovni t’nod
.lohocla gniegnib ffo nrows d’I taht drawretfa kcis os nettog dna keew noitatneiro gnirud eno enod d’I
.gnorw os tlef tsuj tI“
?gniksa neve I ma tahW
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.em ees yllautca nac ohw eno on s’ereht tahT
.yllufhsab daeh ym fo kcab eht bur I ”?huH“
”,erus rof emit txen tub ,t’nac yllaer I“
– mihw a no roloc eht egnahc ot smees ehS
.redduhs I dna elzzum ym no htaerb reh fo tnih tseltbus eht leef I
”.nommoc yllaer s’taht ,sey ,noitseuq ruoy rewsna ot tuB
.tuo reh wollof ot pu teg I neht dna
,edis eht ot ffo ecnalg I dna kcab pit srae yM
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
*	      *	      *   .ytrap eht ot og ot deen I
”.yletanutrofnu ,snalp evah I“ .daeh ym ekahs I
.tuoba klat ot stnaw ilA tahw suoiruc ma I – tsael ta ,eniuneg si noitseuq ehT
I ecnis reve dnim ym fo kcab eht ni neeb s’taht noitseuq eht ksa ot egru neddus a leef I tub
,kcab yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I
– railimaf tub ,dootsrednusim ,enola
.tuo dnats reh ekam hsilop lian gnihctam dna ruf daeh reh fo spit deyd eht tub
siht lla htiw devlovni erom teg ot tnaw yeht fi ediced neht dna daetsni snoitcnuf eht ot emoc ot elpoep wen egaruocne ew yllareneG
,gnihtemos yas ot evah I gniwonk ,tuB
?esol ot evah yllaer I od tahw …tey dnA
,seilper elbas eht
.dnoyeb dna timil lacisyhp ym ot flesym gnihsup
,syawedis tnew taht setad tnecer revo noitaresimmoc
yletamitlu sgniht taht gnizilaer ecaJ htiw
”.tsrif meht ot esolc yllanoitome er’uoy fi elpoep ot detcartta yllauxes eb ylno nac uoy nehw s’taht
,puorg eht fo redael eht nopu deniart seye lla
.rehtet a saw ereht
.yadnuS no ytrap kaerb retniw eht ot pu gniwohs no gninnalp erew uoy fi gnirednow tsuj saw I
.tnemevap eht tsniaga dnuop sdap wap erab yM
.nus noonretfa-dim eht ni snetsilg taht teknalb etihw ynwod a ni derevoc supmac eht gnivael ,detaba ecnis sah mrots ehT
.tniop emos ta gninoitseuq fo ecalp a ni neeb evah su fo ynam taht yas lliw I tuB
.drow rehtona tuohtiw moor eht otni spets dna ti snepo neht
.elpuoc a ylno tuB
.taorht rieht gniraelc enoemos fo dnuos eht ot em dniheb skriuq rae ym
.nosinu ni pu steg enoyreve sa srae evitisnes ym stluassa roolf doowdrah dehsilop eht gnola gnidils sriahc fo ynohpocac A
tluciffid ylsuolirep si ti
.yadot retfa niaga meht otni nur t’ndluow ylekil I – hcum taht erac t’nod I ,yltsenoH
.rof saw teehs pungis eht tahw s’taht sseug I
,leef llits seca od“
.tnelis sniamer enoyreve ,niaga
.hguorht llaf snalp esoht fi yadnuS no uoy ees ot taerg eb dluow ti tub ,gnihtyna ro timmoc ot deen oN
,tuo llac yeht ,don tfiws a htiw
,nosinu ni seybdoog rettum yeht sa srehto eht ta sessik wef a swolb ehS
.gniteem tsal ym si siht taht tcaf eht no delttes ylriaf m’I
”…gnirednow saw I dnA
,retsaf nur I llitS
.sngis teerts skcal taht yawa sdray ytfif tuoba noitcesretni na gnieb thgis ni kramdnal ylno eht htiw
”.won ereh er’uoy taht taerg s’ti tub ,tuo krow t’ndid dennalp dah uoy revetahw taht yrros m’I“
.onaclov tnamrod-gnol a fo ecrof lluf eht htiw tpure I
,sgnikram larutan on sraeb taoc demoorg-llew ,keels s’elbas derruf-krad ehT
.elpuoc a sa ytrap esuoh a ot enog d’ew emit tsrif eht dah inaD woh ekilnu ton ffo em wohs dna – moor gnivil ,moor gninid ,nehctik
staes rieht ni elffuhs elpoep wef A
.dael ekil leef sgel yM
.efil elohw ym ni yldab os eno detnaw reven ev’I
.ebiv gnimoclew ,eltneg a sah tsuj puorg eht dna
.’skcilc‘…tsuj ti tuoba gnihtemoS .ma I woH
”?pu s’tahW .eerf m’I ,oN“
redluohs ym revo kcapkcab ym gnils I
– erab deppirts si luos ym tuB
”tsdiM ruO ni neilA nA“
.evisserppo si eceip ym yas I retfa ecnelis fo tnemom ehT   ”.thgim…ereh
.noos ytterp eb dluohs – semoc doof eht litnu dnuora gnah ot gniog tsuj er’eW
.llah gninid eht ni syart rennid ruo dnuora deldduh ew sa setametius ym ot noitnetta hcum yap I did ron
.yaw hsi-aneyh yllacitsiretcarahc a ni nirg yhtoot a em hsalf neht
– dnuorgkcab eht otni edaf ylurt ot elbissopmi ti gnikam
eno siht piks esaelp
htaerb peed a ekat yllanif nac I nehw keew yreve tnemom detiawa-gnol taht – yadirF .m.p eerhT
.siht ni enola ton er’uoy taht dias I nehw ti tnaem I“
.smaxe tnecer retfa feiler
.kcab gniog on s’ereht ,llebrood taht gnir I ecno tuB
,flesmih ecudortni ot ecnahc a nettog t’nsah eH“
– yltnerehocni elbmum I
.won thgir ereh tub erehwyna eb ot tnaw I taht tcaf eht yawa gnivig morf egaugnal ydob ym peek ot tsedrah ym gniyrt ,yldrawni hgis I
,seye eulb tfos htiw ezag tnesba ym teem ot eunitnoc yeht sA
.mrod eht ot kcab gnipool erofeb strikstuo supmac eht dnuora
.citegolopa snrut noisserpxe reH
,eunitnoc yeht dna ,don thgils a meht evig I
.won em gniypuccoerp sthguoht eht ekil gnihtoN .scipot lamroN
.si ecruos eht tahw ees ot sesuoh rieht fo tuo emoc ot srehtob eno on
”.lla retfa ,’+AIQTBGL‘ ni ’A‘ na s’ereht yhw s’tI
.seiralas erugif-xis sevlesmeht yap ekil
,spih rieht no swap rieht tup dna thgiew rieht stfihs aneyh ehT
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,hguoht ,esirprus ym oT
flesym ot yfitsuj ot redrah dna redrah gnitteg s’ti hguoht neve ,stnemele eht gnivarb ,drawno sserp I llits tuB .em ta sgan
.dnoces siht thgir naem yltcaxe t’ndid I
+TBGL dnuora deretnec seirots gnillet no sesucof ohw rohtua yrruf a ,xoF yT yb
,nur ym morf revo lla eros gnileef llits m’I ,retal sruoh ruof-ytnewT
.esahcrup rof elbaliava won si hcihw
,em morf ecnatsid luftcepser a tpek lla
,yalp dluohs ew semag draob fo rewot gniliec-ot-roolf eht fo hcihw revo noissucsid emos s’erehT
.taorht rieht sraelc aneyh ehT
,esuoh yrots-owt a ot emoc I erofeb setunim net rehtona rof no em sdael SPG ehT
– supmac no nmutuA
,revoc duolc latot s’yadot rednu tub
.peY“ .sdon elbas ehT
.gnihtyna yas t’nseod ehs ,hguoht ,deciton ehs fI
,ecaf reh no krims a fo tsohg eht ees I kniht I
,rood eht tuo ti ekam I erofeb ,revewoH
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,ecnatpecca dnif yllautca ot em rof ytinutroppo ylno eht ebyam si siht taht swonk em fo trap A
– sgniteem ynam sa ni seno tnereffid eerht naht ssel on nees ev’I
.hguorht reh tel ot yaw eht fo tuo kcud ylkciuq I os ,rood eht gnikcolb saw I taht dezilaer t’ndah I ”!hO“
.dad regdab yldduc
.tnuocca yrruFoS sih no
”.kniht d’uoy naht su fo erom tol a era erehT
.sdaor gnidniw fo ezam siht etagivan ot tuo enohp ym ekat I sa ecap ym nekciuq I ,niaga ecno tnemevap no nwod hcuot swap ym sa feiler fo hgis llams a gnihtaerB
.esruoc tnereffid a gnola ylthgils os reve em gnigdun
,rettal eht si ti fi dna ,ton od uoy ro
,haH“ .yltfos selkcuhc aeB ,esirprus ym oT
.noissucsid eht ni nioj ot trats neve I
.gnignellahc ylralucitrap sevorp supmac fo edis tsew eht no
.erofeb supmac fo trap siht ot neeb reven ev’I
.tsom em seracs taht tnemgduj rieht ton s’tI
.eromyna gnidih ton m’I esuaceb s’ti taht em stih tI
,ilA yb deteerg m’I dna nepo nworht steg rood eht ,semihc lleb eht retfa sdnoces evif toN
.drawretfa reh ot eybdoog tuo ekohc ylerab dluoc I
”.ecaJ em llac nac uoy tub ,haeY“
,’sixa‘ nwo sti no stsixe yllacisab tahT
”.ecnahc a su evig ll’uoy tniop emos ta taht epoh I ,hguorht gniog er’uoy si ti revetahw oS
.swonk eh enoyreve morf tnereffid yrev s’eh taht ylno
.yadot ton tub ,yaw eht gnola skaerb ekat ot decrof ton m’I taht os neve ecap ym peek ot yrt d’I yllamroN
.dum htiw dekac snaej ym htiw pu wohs ot gnissarrabme dnoyeb neeb evah dluow ti – oot ,gniht dooG
,semit lareves em ta gnicnalg aeB hctac I
,aneyh desserd ylthgirb eht dnif ot dnuora nrut I
.der noen si s’yadot dna
,em ot sregnarts etelpmoc era mohw fo lla ,ereh srebmem fo tol a era ereht elihw dnA .ecnatpecca eurt
.gnivaeh si tsehc yM
.cibohportsualc leef em ekam sklawedis eht revo gnihcterts shguob nedal-eldeen ,esned eht
.gnimlehwrevo oot tsuj er’yeht – noisulcnoc emas eht ot dnuora emac syawla I
– si eh yaw eht si eh yhw dnatsrednu t’nseod eH
epahs ’L‘ na ni dezinagro ylhguor si supmac ehT
”,KO gniod m’I .haeY ?kniht I ,doog…mM“
.gniteem elohw eht nrow d’yeht ecaf rieht no elims neve ,emas taht
”!uoy ees ot doog os s’tI !ecaJ“
.emac ti sa ylkciuq sa sehsinav ti tub
.si siht reverehw morf kcab em ediug nac SPG eht
.eb dluow ti depoh d’I sa lufrednow sa tib yreve s’tI
.uoy dnuora enoyreve morf trapa leef ot ekil s’ti tahw wonk su fo llA
.em ot secaf wen era wef a tub ,sgniteem eht morf ezingocer I ereh elpoep eht fo tsoM
,nees reve ev’I lufituaeb tsom eht
”.hguor yllaer neeb evah tsum tahT .dneirflrig-xe ruoy tuoba yrros m’I ,wonk
.sgnimoctrohs nwo ym fo rednimer a sa devres ylno rehto hcae no gnidnirg selpuoc fo snezod eht taht pleh t’ndid tI
,seunitnoc dna elims llams a em sevig ehS
,tsiaw ym dnuora gut sti leef dluoc I tub
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
gnisuoh namssalcreppu eht morf sgnidliub cimedaca eht gnitarapes llih peets eht nwod gnioG
.rood tnorf eht ot spets wef eht pu klaw dna yawevird eht nwod yaw ym evaew I sa traeh gnidnuop ym ydaets ot yrt I .ti si sihT
.gninnirg ,yas I ”,haeY“
”-eH .dnuora ecaJ nees ylbaborp evah skeew owt tsap eht sgniteem lareneg eht ta neeb evah ohw uoy fo lla ,oS“
.flesti otnu murtceps a yllacisab si ytilauxesA“
– arbegla raenil nmaddog
.gniteem tsrif eht ta nevig d’I noitcudortni enil-eno eht morf eman ym derebmemer yllautca yeht taht desirprus tahwemos ,don I
.tnereffid on s’yadot ,yletanutrof
.ni pu werg I eno eht naht sretniw rehsrah neve sah taht etats a ni egelloc a esoohc ot dah tsuj I
.doof reh ta skcip ehs sa devreser ylddo
.gniksa fo tnemssarrabme eht em deraps dna mret eht denialpxe ehs taht lufetarg m’I
.ria rof psag sgnul yM
?aeB saw ti kniht I ,trohs saw eman esohw
.yawa tlem ot strats ytirucsbo ni gnireffus fo edaced a ylraen fo thgiew eht dna ,em dnuora smra rieht parw aneyh eht tel I
– ffo deleep flah si ’C‘ eht hguoht ,721-C mooR – rood eht fo tnorf ni gnidnats yllanif m’I nehW
,lluP lanoitativarG
”.teehs pungis eht no t’nsi eman ruoy taht deciton I
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ysae taht edam reve thgieh eno-toof-xis ym taht ton
”.ysub er’uoy fi peek ot tnaw t’nod I ?emit dab a siht sI“ .snediw nirg riehT ”.neht ,ecaJ“
,elcric eht ni gnittis ylteiuq era su fo os ro net eht ,retal setunim wef A
.gnihton gnidloh m’I wonk I hguoht neve ,swap ym ot nwod ecnalg ylevixelfer I
,tnemegnarra siht nopu detsisni puorg eht ,yletanutrofnU
.hcuoc eht dnuora klaw ot strats dna taes reh morf pu steg ehs neht
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     ”.ot evol d’I“
.ereh gnoleb yletulosba seca tuB
– slrig ekil od I kniht I – loohcs hgih ni dneirflrig a dah I
,wodniw eht hguorht srebmem bulc eht fo seniltuo ybbolb eht ees ylno nac I .esuap I
ylhguoroht os em detsuahxe dnekeew siht kcultop eht tuoba od ot detnaw I tahw tuo erugif ot gniyrt dna
.yaw eht gnola erehwemos noitcerid dna emit htob fo kcart esol I   .eerf m’I
.dneirflrig a tnaw od I .ti yllaer t’nsi…tahT“
.emoc d’I semit owt tsal eht ekil tsuj
.elims deniarts a htiw daeh reh gnikahs
,rethgit meht dloh I
– sdauq gnilwarps eht fo hcni yreve gnirevoc neewteb ni gnihtyreve dna
.yawyna ti deksir evah dluow ylbaborp I ,hguoht ,gnileef m’I woh neviG
.ylgninoitseuq em ta kcab skool aneyh ehT
,elgna latnoziroh-raen a ta em gnittih sekalfwons fo yrrulf a yb dedrabmob m’I
.dias tsuj yeht tahw brosba ot enola em gnivael
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.tey em nees evah dluow eno oN
.daeh ym gnitnac ,ylper I
– saera nommoc roolf-tsrif eht dnuora em dael yehT
.no og ot flesym ecrof I tuB
– sklawedis dna sdaor eht gnici-ed dna yawa gniraelc tsael ta htiw doog ytterp yllausu era swerc ecnanetniam eht ,wons ni deirub teg ew taht si ti nommoc woh htiW
I“ .nwod og ot sesufer ylnrobbuts dnuora klat ot gnilggurts m’I taorht ym ni pmul ehT
.woble eht ta tuoba m’I dna
.noitcerid wen elohw a ni ffo reev I ro
,syas ehs ,tohsrae fo tuo dna rood tnorf eht ot teg ew nehW
,emit eht ta neeb dah I sa erus sa ,si hturt ehT
.niap ehT .egar ehT
.skcals dna trihs deralloc ym htiw desserdrevo tahwemos m’I yltnerappa
.yltsenoh ylper neht
,retsemes siht scisyhp namhserf gnikat htob er’ew taht dna
,ylper yeht ,emit tsrif eht rof gniretlaf elimS
.sdnekeew eht no nwo ym no ylegral m’I taht snaem taht
*	      *	      *   .moor eht fo tuo yaw ym ekam dna dnuora nrut ot hguone flesym tcelloc nac I erofeb owt ro etunim a s’tI
W“ ,rettuts I ,gnihtyna
.daeh ym ekahs ylwols I nehT .niaga etatiseh I
?detsugsiD ?desufnoC ?dekcohs yeht erA
.em dna ilA no era seye llA
.niaga rehto eht ot tuo hcaer lliw su fo rehtie taht tcepxe t’nod I
,eunitnoc yeht neht ,ylwols don I
.elihwhtrow pirt eht ekam ot naht nosaer rehto on rof fi ,yats llew sa thgim I
weN rof llac enohp etunim-net a
”.lla ta taht ni enola ton er’uoY
– erahs t’nod I gnihtemos yb detcennoc yllatnemadnuf era ohw
– yleritne supmac eht tfel ev’I ebyam ro
– ezingocer t’nod I supmac fo aera na ni m’I
”.detrats teg s’tel neht ,thgir llA“
– leef I thgil woh eveileb yldrah nac I
– gnitliw flesym leef I
– mretdim gniworrah ytterp a dehsinif tsuj ev’I sa
– elcric eht dnuora gnicnalg
uoY“ .suoires snrut noisserpxe reh erofeb em ta selims ylfeirb ehS ”.dalg m’I“
,eciov fo enot reraelc a ni yas I ,niaga srehto eht gnidrageR
.ylgnigaruocne em ta elims yehT
,esrevinu eht ni enola ton m’I taht epoh ehT
– pirt nruter eht ot rehtona dda I ,retnec tneduts eht sdrawot ekat I pets yreve rof
– htap trid eht no gnitoof ym esol ylraen I ,era yeht sa ffits sgeL
– taht lla retfa detsuahxe ssel on leef I
.sksa ehs ”?sgniht fo sdnik tahW“
,noitcartta lauxes fo level emos leef seca emoS
.dnim rieht no yllaer s’tahw gniyas redisnoc ot mees yeht sa pu gnihcnurcs elzzum trohs rieht ,sesuap ilA
.enoyreve ,emocleW“
”!yadnuS no kcultop eht ta uoy ees ot epoh I !enoyreve ,kaerb taerg a evah ,neht thgir llA“
.tnorf tuo dekrap srac eht lla rof evas srobhgien sti morf tcnitsidni
.saw sraey rof dnuora gniyrrac neeb ev’I tahw suomrone woh tsuj ezilaer I od ecnesba sti ni ylno
,moor eht fo tuo edirts dna kcilf liat regae na em evig yeht ,don I nehW   ”?ti tuoba knihT
thgin eht yag eb thgim I taht noitseggus s’inaD
.dedeen fi ,ni doof eht yrrac pleh ot rood tnorf eht ot em dna
.ni tif uoy snaem ecalp tsrif eht ni ereh emoc ot dediced uoy taht tcaf ehT“
.elbissop sa emit doog a fo aedi ym morf yawa raf sa tuoba saw ti
”.em tsurt ,ereht tuo elpoep tseiknik eht fo emos era secA“ .ni snael ehS
trapa llef sgniht
.flehs eht ffo ecnaraeppa ’egatniv‘ a meht evig ot snoitacol esicerp ni dedaf dna deppir – os ylbanoihsaf tub ,ygnurg era sehtolc reH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
taht – oiranecs laedi ym htiw pu denil dah ytilaer fi ecin neeb evah dluow ti ,eruS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,flesruoy ees nac uoy hcihw ni yrots yna draeh reven evah uoy nehw
.emoh og dna dnuora nrut ot emit llits s’ereht – gnicar si dnim yM
,kcab pirt eht no mrotswons gniogno eht tlef ylerab I
.tser no tuo dexam ylgnimees ,yhctiwt teg ot gnitrats si ydob ym tub
.shtnom fo elpuoc txen eht rof ti hguor ot evah tsuj ll’I sseug I os
.thgin tsal tiucric ytrap tarf elohw eht gniod retfa srevognah gnisrun ylekil era supmac no llits stneduts fo ytirojam eht
.moor gnivil eht otni kcab yaw ruo ekam ew
.gnidliub eht fo kcab yrev eht ot yaw ym ekam I sa elit muelonil eht no stneduts rehto yb tfel hsuls fo selddup eht diova ot yrt I
.meht fo lluf ecaf a gnitteg diova ot kcud ot evah I ecno naht eroM
.sdap wap ym otni setib klawedis yci ehT
.won oga gnol os sleef dna shtnom fo elpuoc a ylerab detsal dah
– ”,hu ,I .siht tuoba tol a wonk ot mees uoy ,os…yeH“
– edis rehtie no wons
.yas ot evah t’nod uoy
.ecalp s’ilA ot yaw ym ekam I sa sniap dna sehca eht erongi I tub
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
”.yllaer ,gnihton saw ti ,llew…tsuj I ,oN“
.lamron er’yeht taht kniht t’nod I taht si ygolopa na morf ekat ll’yeht tahw taht ezilaer ot ylno
”?tnemom a rof moor gnivil eht ni rehtag lla uoy dluoc ,enoyrevE“
,rehtie gnihtyna yas t’nod I ,tey dnA
.ylf ot nigeb I neht dnA
.eseht ot gniog neeb ev’I yhw
,sseug I ,won ti revo…m’I .haey…ho-
.su neewteb elbacima sgniht peek ot deganam d’ew tub
– spihsnoitaler citnamor ni detseretni t’nera yeht
.skcit fo elpuoc a nwod etartraeh ym gnirb seod erutseg eht etacorpicer yldrawkwa I sa leef I htmraw eht tub ,wen enoemos teerg ot yaw railimaf ylddo na sa em sekirts tI
,leef em ekam dluohs taht derussaer woh ni ksab yllaer nac I erofeB
.seye rieht gnillor meht ees ot revo kool I dna
”.reilrae looc ytterp saw tahT“
.reh devol yllaer I hguoht neve
.htiw pleh rof elpoep rehto no yler ylirassecen t’nac ew taht seussi no yllaicepse
.tsenoh eb ot ,em ot hcum laeppa t’ndid tI
”?thgir ,gnihtyna ni detseretni t’nera dna rentrap a evah ot tnaw t’nod uoy nehw s’tahT“   .s’aeB s’ti
.gniog fo noitnetni on evah I esruoc fo tub ,eil a s’tahT
.nur a otni tuo kaerb I neht dna ,edirts ym dnif I hguone noos tub ,tsrif ta ehca sgel yM
,goj ksirb a otni tuo kaerb I ,pu pmarc ll’I kniht t’nod I taht hguone rebmil leef I ecnO
.em rof thgir enoemos dnif dluow I wenk ehs taht saw pu gnuh ew erofeb htiw em tfel d’ehs gniht tsal ehT
.neeb reve ev’I naht retteB
nworb ot der ot egnaro ot wolley morf gnignar sedahs fo sevael htiw
– etuc reh dnuof syawla ev’I
.kaeps ot os ,’tuo emac‘
.retnec tneduts eht gnisuoh gnidliub yarg ,tauqs eht edisni tam detaeh a no swap ym gniyrd dna snaej ym fo smeh eht morf wons eht gnikconk m’I
,retal gniklaw ymoolg fo setunim eviF
.yadretsey nur eht morf mrod ym ot kcab flesym deggard I ecnis reve ti tuoba gnikniht neeb t’nevah I taht ton ,yas ot tnaw I tahw aedi on evah I
”.elbuort hcum oot ton s’ti epoh I…haey-
.eno hcihw erus ton m’I hguohtla
”!em dnif dna emoc ,gnihtyna deen uoy fI
– tuohguorht noitnetta fo tuo dna ni gnitfird flesym dnif I
,moor otni elffuhs stseug os ro nezod eht sa pots su dnuora no gniog snoitasrevnoc lareves ehT
.lliw su fo enon esimorp I .yrp ot gniog ton m’I“
– ?eb ton ereht dluoc woh dna
.nottub eht sserp dna drawrof hcaer ylwols I ,gnikahs waP
ylla thgiarts a gnieb
ev’yehT .degduj eb t’now I taht ecnarussaer s'ilA eveileb od I
.kaerb gnol-keew eht rof ni delttes teg dna ,sdneirf ym htiw llah gninid eht ot daeh d’I ,taht retfA
.kcultop a eb ot desoppus saw siht…thgir s’tahT
.oot KO yllatot s’taht ,hguoht ,ton er’uoy fI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.hguorht dereffus dna decneirepxe ev’I tahw swonk ohw
”.ekil yllaer s’ti tahw fo noisserpmi gnidaelsim a gnitteg er’uoy esuaceb siht fo trap a gnieb morf degaruocsid teg ot gniog er’uoy taht denrecnoc m’I“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.yawllah worran eht nwod dap I sa edis rehtie no em dnuorrus
.ylgnirussaer ylper yeht ”,KO s’tahT“
.tnaw uoy fi ,egdirf eht ni sreeb emos eb llits dluohs erehT .knird a barg ot eerf leef ,lleW“
.ecaJ m’I ,dias ilA sa ,llew-
.elbmum I ”?ilA ,hu-
,seirots
,gniteem tsrif ym ta noitcudortni feirb a morf edisA
,levon ecnamor yag htgnel-lluf a dehsilbup yltnecer sah eH
,flesym retnec-er ot yrt ot eganam nac I sa nur a fo gnol sa rof og dna staews emos no worht ot ediced I os ,eludehcs peels ym gnitpursid rehtruf tuohtiw eeffoc a barg ot won etal oot s’tI
.noitome fo llew taht gnippat ot pu leef t’nod I tub ,hturt eht morf raf s’tahT
.tuo trulb I ”?yllaeR“
,etad yaD s’enitnelaV a gnirud meht neewteb daeh a ot emac sgnihT
.puorg eht fo trap a eb ot ylla ylno eht eb t’ndluow uoy ,thgiarts dna sic er’uoy fi nevE
.wap rieht otno gnidloh peek I tub ,evael ot nrut yehT
.tlobrednuht a yb kcurts neeb ev’I ekil s’tI
.ereh yllanif si dnekeew eht taht feiler eht ni ksab dna
.dias uoy tahw tuoba thguoht I ,llew ,mre …I“
.emit ym fo esu elihwhtrow a si ereh gnimoc taht flesym ecnivnoc ot redrah dna redrah semoceb ti sa nekrad ot eunitnoc sthguoht ym ,elihw eht lla
.gnilaever oot ,hcum oot si siht
– llew rehto hcae wonk ydaerla ohw sregnarts fo hcnub a htiw llehs ym fo tuo decrof gnieb dna flesym yb pu gniwohs fo tcepsorp eht dna
.retsum nac I ygrene eht lla htiw sguh rieht fo hcae nruter I tub
.raeb ralop detsehc-lerrab a fo ecarbme eht ni pu thguac flesym dnif I erofeb
.roputs ym fo tuo em raj em dniheb taorht s’enoemos fo gniraelc eht dna redluohs ym no pat thgil A
.daor niam eht ot yaw ym ekam yldeirruh dna spets enots dlo-raey-derdnuh nwod dnuob I
.yb zzihw nrob saw I erofeb gnol detcere sesuoh ytekcir dna seert fo snoteleks nedal-wonS
.paeh gnitnap a ni dnuorg dloc eht no espalloc I neht dna
”.gninnigeb eht ecnis siht fo trap a neeb
.era srehto eht fo snoitcaer eht tahw ees ot flesym gnirb ot elbanu ,roolf eht no nwod dexif ezag ym peek I
”!enoyreve ot uoy ecudortni em teL !hO“
elbat moor gninid eht raelc pleh ot nehctik eht ot gniog reh
.skeehc ym nwod wolf ot nigeb yllanif gniddehs morf flesym peek ot gniyrt neeb ev’I sraet eht dna
”?si ytilauxesa tahw wonk uoy od ,ecaJ“
,spil ym evael sdrow eht sa noos sa noitpmussa dlob a sa em sekirts tahT
– del ti erehw llet t’ndluoc I
Y“ .ylevitatnet tib a tiebla ,kcab elims I
,knis nehctik eht ni setalp ysaerg rieht dekcats dna gnitae dehsinif s’enoyreve nehW
.em nihtiw pu llew ot yteixna sesuac ecnelis ehT
,noitatirri ni rae reh skcilf ehS ”?dnim uoy od
retal raey enO  2 fo
”?thgir ,nosaJ“ ,syas ilA ,eciov fo enot yldneirf a nI
dnuora nrut ot ecnahc a evah ylerab I tub ,og em stel ilA
,dnopser yeht ,yletaidemmi pu gnikreP
.rae ot rae morf gninnirg er’yeht taht ees I ,kcab pets a ekat dna em esaeler yllanif yeht nehw dna
”.tnemgduj tuohtiw ksa nac uoy erehw ecalp a si siht
.em ot gnimoc t’nera llits sdrow eht
,yad gniwollof eht hguone llew leef ohw meht fo elpuoc eht htiw semag oediv gniyalp ro laem a gnihctac ebyam morf edisA
,kaerc ot trats enips ym leef I taht ylthgit os em sezeeuqs eH
– dnuora ecnalg I sa tuoba gnillim elpoep wef yrev ees I
aera dedoow ylivaeh a dnuora sdniw taht shtap regnol ym fo eno gnola gnitrats
.em dniheb tuhs sgniws rood eht sa swap ym morf trid eht epiw ot ecnahc a em gnivig ylerab ,edisni em gut dna tsirw ym fo dloh barg yeht ,tcaer ot ecnahc a evah I erofeB
”?ereh m’I yhw …wonk ot tnaw thgim uoy taht
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
hcus tuohtiW .siht sa hcus yrots a ,eseht sa hcus seirots llet ot hguone denimreted saw ohw enoemos ot sknaht si ti neht yhw
– ni detseretni yldlim m’I taht gnidnif m’I lrig a ot enola tel
,gnihtyna yas ot gniog si eno on taht raelc semoceb ti nehW
.meht hguorht ssap I sa eson ym tew elahxe hcae morf ropav gnisnednoc fo sffup ehT
.rulb a ni yb dessap yad eht fo tser ehT
.ylevissimsid wap rieht sevaw aneyh eht ,ygolopa na elbmum nac I erofeb tub ,daeh ym ekahs dna ylhsipeehs daeh ym fo kcab eht bur I   .tihS
.tuo daeh attog ev’I tub ,ilA yrros m’I“
,evig ot detnaw I naht erom rof em gnisserp peek eH .yug a htiw pihsnoitaler a ni saW“
”.kaerb gnirps erofeb tsuj siht ekil tuonrut ees ot taerg s’tI
.htiw detcennoc yllanoitome er’yeht elpoep ot ylno tub
.evresbo ylpmis dna dnuorgkcab eht otni edaf tsael ta nac I ,ereH
”?neht gniteem txen eht ta uoy ees ll’I ,thgir llA“
.sruoh eerht rehtona rof tuo ssap dna deb ni kcab m’I 11 yb tub ,01 litnu pu teg t’nod I
,sgalf cificeps-noitatneiro ynam eht fo eno fo sroloc eht sa meht ezingocer I
?ereh gniod neve I ma tahW
noitartsurf dna noisufnoc reh desserpxe ehs erehw
.yllufetarg meht ta don I
”?sthguoht tsal ynA“
”?ti si ,ereh er’uoy nosaer eht t’nsi
.rof sdrow eht dnif ot gniyrt skeew nekat ev’I tahw setunim net ot evif txen eht ni tuo erugif ll’I hguoht sa ton s’ti ,niaga nehT
.rae ym ni tnemegaruocne fo sdrow gnirepsihw emos
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,htiw railimaf erom m’I supmac fo trap nrehtron eht naht ereh seert enip erom era erehT
,emit siht tpecxE
”.yaw ralimis a fo dnik ni trapa llef ti ,yawynA“
,god.ecioveht ta
,drawkwa ylbidercni si lla ta siht gnisolcsid
,yenom noitiut ruo htiw od ot sgniht retteb dah evah tsum srotartsinimda ehT
.seod esle enoyreve ekil yldnof em sguh dna selims ehS
”.rehtegot eniltuo na tog ylerab ev’I dna gninrom worromot eud yassE
.gnihtyna syas su fo enon esiwrehto tub ,hguoc a tuo stel eno dna
.taht tuoba yrroS“
– meht ta kool ot daeh ym nrut I
,ecnalg sseldrow a egnahcxe eW
.dedulcni enim ,era smrod namhserf eht fo lla erehw dne htron eht ,tfel ym oT
?sgniteem fo elpuoc a tsuj morf evarc yldab os I gnignoleb fo esnes eht leef d’I taht tcepxe ot ti saw riaf woh tuB
.trons tfos a tuo stel ehS
,yawa selim derdnuh neetfif loohcs ot gniog saw ehs tuB .em reh dna
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,xoF yT yb
– ti fo retteb kniht nac I erofeb dna
– reh devol llits I
.tneitapmi ylgnisaercni gniworg flesym dnif I tub ,setunim wef a sekat ylno tI
.ksa yeht ”?gnihtyna gnirb uoy diD .lla ta toN“
,ecafrus eht ot pu selbbub sraey dna skeew dna yad tsap eht rof gniremmis neeb sah taht gnihtyreve
– em ot lleb a gnir t’nod seman ehT
.regnol yna deb ym fo trofmoc eht morf em gnipeek gnihton s’ereht tsael ta ,saw siht sa gnitnioppasid sA
raey ym ni yllautca si ,evaD ,raeb ralop eht taht tuo semoc ti nehW
”.ylkciuq ytterp yb seog tI .oobaT fo emag eno ,no emoC“ .nworf yehT
.lamron…ton m’I taht si wonk I llA
,ecnalg deye-edis suoiruc a em seraps ehS
.em dniheb siht lla tup dna
.tfel evah I lla si
”tsdiM ruO ni neilA nA“
– noitasrevnoc eht ni tniop hcnarb eht si siht taht esnes I
”,esneffo yna naem t’ndid ,yrros-S“ ,tuo remmats I
.tuo meht kcip ot elba eb t’ndluow yletinifed I ,sgniteem eseht gnidnetta neeb ev’yeht fi
,sgniteem owt suoiverp eht ni em derehtob dah eno on ,llitS
derugif I ,sseug I-
,srebmun moor rieht fo tniap kcalb dedaf eht rof evas rehtona eno morf elbahsiugnitsidni ,swodniw ssalg detsorf htiw srood nedooW
.gnihctiwt era sreksihw enif reh yaw etuc eht yb detcartsid m’I esuaceb tuo sdrow eht teg ot drah s’ti
.ruoh na flah ni si gniteem puorg +AIQTBGL supmac ehT
,seititnedi dna snoitatneiro fo murtceps daorb a gnitneserper stneduts fo noitilaoc siht gnoma neve
”.gniog peek…tsuJ .enif s’ti ,ecaJ“
.dnats tser eht elihw safos rehtael nrow no staes gnikat emos
.xes gnivah elbatrofmoc leef llits yam t’nod ohw esohT
,sevirra yllanif gnirps taht yaM litnu eb t’now ti nemssalcreppu yb dlot neeb ev’I
daeh ym revo akrap ym fo dooh eht llup ot em gnicrof
.yawyna azzip fo hcnub a gniredro no gninnalp erew ew dna togrof elpoep eht flaH .ti tuoba yrrow t’noD“
,si naem I tahW“
ev’yeht dna teh htob era eciralC dna ynneB
.dlot eb tsum siht ekil ,dias neeb sah sa ,seirotS  .dad regdab yldduc