,tnuh ot ereh uoy gnirb t’ndid I“ .ti derewol dna
ym tup ot gnirehtob tuohtiw retnuh txen eht yfsitas dna tnuom dna dnuora nrut neht
,htooms dna tfos s’ti
.retaw rof deksa eh fi sa deppuc ,swap htob tuo dehcaer arakaS ”.taht htiw hguone mraw eb ll’ew erus m’I
,esolc ni denael ikkuT .kcab sih no elbarenluv dna dekan yal ohw xof eht revo gninael
,erew yeht detnioppasid woh rettam on ,esuaceB
”?gnihtemos ro smrow tug evah uoy rebmemer tsuj uoY“
”sthgiR gniggarB“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,lla ti ni tsol neeb dah oot eH
,noisufnoc dna htlaets lla ,dah eH
,goj a otni meht derrups siht llA
,dum eht revo dekan krats yllacitcarp deppiks dna deppoh yeht sa ydaets llits teef s’tuocs dlo eht
,flowcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb ”sthgiR gniggarB“
,gnorw toof a tup uoy fi sknuhc etihw yklim drah otni delbmurc taht enots der lla ,ffulb eht fo edis eht dnuorA
,yaws ot nageb liat s’xof eht ,yldeticxE
.ni tes etibtsorf eht ecno seot rieht ekil hcum ,tsol eb dluow ruf ytaews rieht ot gnulc taht egdol taews eht fo htmraw eht ro
,yrgnuh saw ecarbme s’retto ehT .smra sih otni pu kcab arakaS dellup dna detnurg ikkuT
.lortnoc peek ot gnihcnelc daeh sih fo edis rehtie no shgiht retto ykcots leef dluoc arakaS dna
”.did uoy taht llems nac I“
…sa ebircsed ylno dluoc arakaS tahw etisoppo delip lla wob & reviuq ytpme na ,sraeps fo eldnub A
”,ereht thgir ,xof ,ti s’tahT“
.arakaS hguorht erusaelp fo evaw a tnes noissap s’retto eht fo borht dna ,ezeeuqs hcae
,kcab dellup neht
,kcoc s’xof eht neffits ot dekrow ylno tI
:yhw ees dluoc eh dnA
,stoor ssarg eht ta gnikcip tuoba llim ot egde s’retaw eht tfel eseeg eht sa gnirats ,tas dah ikkuT ”.ihovatneL eht gnoma retnuh tseb eht neeb evah I
,ffurcs s’arakaS otni kcab eson sih degnulp eh sa dennirg ikkuT ”,tnemhserfer elttil a deen I fi dnA“
,nwod deid ti ecnO
dehtuom-gib sih lla rof
ffits saw tfahs s’arakaS
,nam a neeb ev’uoy naht regnol roF“
,arakaS rof ylno nwod decnalg eH
,tcnitsni denoh ylprahs tey ,tneicna emos yb dnA
,egdol s’namahs eht ni devil anaS taht won
,pu thgir tohs liat s’xof ehT
,ekorts hcaE .derahs
”,eb lliw ti ebyam dnA“
…emit tsrif ruoy siht sI“
,taht ekil tsuj dna
,demriuqs dna denaom eH
,drawrof despalloc dna delrans ikkuT .tnemom a rof
.efas meht speek taht tcnitsni dliw eht ekahs t’nac sniarb rieht tub
,tnemmoc ot no tnew ikkuT sa
.regnif a htiw mih decnelis retto eht tub
,ylenol eb dluow ronoC ,dias dah eh
,rehtegot-teg tsal rieht eb yldrah dluow siht tuB .tnemtnioppasiD
fo mortslam a ni delriws dnim eh sa sdrow eht dnif ot elbanu
.tsehc sih tsniaga ydob mraw a tub
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.erom detnaw yldab os eh dna
”?ti tuoba em llet“
,ylpeed delahni arakaS "…I"
arakaS nehw deudbus yllausunu erew sakajraH dna ,äemheP ,telouH
”?em gnillet uoy era yhw oS“
.ylevitcnitsni esor kcen sih no selkcah eht elihw elgnit enips sih ekam dna
.seldduc thgit dna
,ecnedifnoc lluf drawot kcab mih dekorts yltneg
.redlo ylerem ,thgin taht emit tsrif eht rof ,dnuos t’ndid eH
.erofeb kcoc s’nam rehtona nekat reven dah eh ,lla retfA
,tuh tsal eht dednuor yeht sa tuB
.shgiht sih neewteb ro tsehc sih tsniaga elzzum sih sserp t’ndid
.llaw eht tsniaga mih gnidworc ronoC oN
,kcab shtnom emoS
.desufnoc ,deknilb arakaS ”?tahw enoD“
niav ni depsarg dna
.ereh saw eh yhw mih dnimer ot sreksihw sih ot gnulc llits gnoht s'ikkuT fo tnecs eht fo sparcs hguone
.saw ylbaborp ti tahw wonk ot tsap sih tuoba hguone wenk retnuh eht tub
.psarg sih morf deppils htgnel evisserpmi sih sa desruc dna
,retto sselnoissap eht fo thgis eht ta gniknis traeh sih ,dnA
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.won saw tnemom eht wenk eh
,ecneirepxe gnol fo taews eht fo
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.deksa ikkuT ”?daem deirt reve uoY“
,swap s’xof eht tsniaga mlap sih decalp dna tuo dehcaer ikkuT ,nrut nI .simuK rO
.kle llat ro reed rof ssarg on ,skcor dna selbmarb lla saw dnuorg eht
,osrot s’xof eht fo edis rehtie no delbmert smra s’retto eht
,kool a ekat dna resolc peerc dluoc eh erofeb ,revewoH
.akkeP morf detnuomsid eh nehw deksa dah arakaS
.erehwon morf pu esor yteixna peed a dna
,mih fo trap yreve edam tI
.htuom s’retto eht otni eugnot sih dehsup dna
.skeehc wolloh hguorht htaerb detartsurf a welb ikkuT .lufyalp dna
.depoh eh ,ylgnitivnI
,feihc eht yb ton yllaicepsE
”.erofeb enod ton d’I gniht eno naht erom em dewohs eH
”…mH“ .ydaerla smra s’aneyh eht ni yllacitcarp saw eh
.ycnetop sti eziminim ot kniht dluow renwo sti taht tsetorp ni fi sa
.elzzum s’arakaS no wap eltneg a dial aneyh eht ”,dnim t’nod I“
”?yawyna ,rof ereh tuo em gnirb uoy did tahW“
”?hcuop nikskcub a nrow reve uoy …tub
,ecalp siht dnif ot woh swonk retnuh eno sa gnol sA“
.ylirgnuh detnurg retto eht ”.ti enod s’tahT“
,gnitfihs saw elam redlo ehT
”-tnaw uoy fi ,ronoC“
.elohekoms eht hguorht yks yrrats eht otni gnitoohs mih evah dluow tsul sih deraef eh fi sa hgiht eht yb xof eht debbarg dna htgnel sih deppord ikkuT ,esirprus yb thguaC
.mih ecarbme t’ndid ,redlo tub
,htuom sih erofeb regnif a htiw mih dehsuh dah ikkuT ,rewsna na naht rehtaR
,ereht devil esle eno on taht tcaf eht tnereffid woh tub
”?ti si ,liat ruoy yb dekan emoh uoy deggard I nehw detcepxe uoy tahw toN“
.esle ydobon was yeht taht ykcul meht detnuoc arakaS .wons dna ,kcor
,shtuom s’rehtohcae detsat yeht nehT
detaroballoc ev’yeht emit hcae rof rallod a dah yeht fi ohw
,tserup dna tsegnorts eht syawla s’ti erehw sgel s’nam a neewteb ecalp eht ta ,luos sih
,sgniht did yllausu eh yaw eht t’nsaw sihT
pil sih tib ikkuT
.flesti wohs t’now ti tub
.elohekoms s’uvvaL eht nwod enohs dna noom eht ffo detcelfer hcihw taht sediseb
.egdol taews eht ni maets ekil
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
,skcottub dna sniol mraw fO
,gnizarg fo sngis oN
eht htaeneb tsuj ,tub
!enoyna gnillet og t’nod
.sebirt nwo rieht morf yawa erew yeht elihw
.wollof ot arakaS rof derutseg neht dna
,teem edart txen eht ta neve spahreP
,eseht sediseB .wonk ton did eh
elbaton erom gnihtyna od ot tfel dah rehtien fi sa
,ycavirp neddus eht yhW
.rewsna na rof gnitiaw tuohtiw no tnew ikkuT tub
”?ti ekaw lliw tahW“
,uvvaL eht otni delip arakaS dna ikkuT
tuhs nworht saw yawyrtne eht derevoc taht palf ehT
eht morf nopaew sih gnitniona enod won neve saw ikkuT nehw
,ytilanosrep gniogtuo netfo s’ikkuT ,hguohT .retto eht truh thgim sdrow eht woh fo thguoht hcum tuohtiw ,desaet äemheP
.yamsid htiw kcoc tcere yltrap ylno sih ta nwod derats eh elihw lla
gnuoY saW dlroW eht nehW ni yltnecer tsom
kcoc sih dnuora wam mraw a rof t’nerew stsul sih fi sa
,retto eht dnuora depparw ffulf retniw htiw yvaeh liat egral sih
.dehcuot tsomla seson rieht taht esolc os
.rethgit shgiht sih dezeeuqs dna delkcuhc ikkuT hcihw ot
,esaerg raeb fo raj elttil
.tnecs taht fo ffins gnol a koot dna
,pmuj em edam uoy
evitisiuqni htob saw taht kool a htiw edis eht ot dekcoc daeh sih
,ezeeuqs hcae ,ekorts hcaE
?truh dluow ti wonk ot eh saw woh
.anuas eht ni ekawa saw tI“
.dlo dednuos eH
.pal s’ikkuT ni ylmrif decalp esra erab sih dna
.esabliat sih rednu deddorp enots sa drah kcoc nehw dedda eh ”.taht ,hO“
.erom ekat dluow eh dnA
.tnemom eht ta tuoba derac yllaer eh lla saw taht
.ti delzzun ylregae ohw xof eht dna
.drah detnap eh sa gnivaeh tsehc sih
.no won morf eb dluow ti yaw eht rehtar tub
,retto eht yb noitativni na saw tI
,won nesohc dah nomed ro ecrof neesnu emos taht demees ti dnA
.spohc sih dekcil dna deooc retto eht
.elbaecalperri dna suoicerp gnihtemos evreserp dna
.lluks sih fo kcab eht otni gnillor tsomla seye eulb-citcra
,ti deirt yllautca reven ev’I
,noitarepsed fo rekcilf elgnis a saw meht fo kcab eht tA
,deremmats dna derettuts arakaS ”-t’nsaw I ,tsuj I“
ereh emac seitrap gnitnuh fi tub
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.sseldrager mih rof yrros tlef arakaS ,demees ti os rO
,denrecnoc dnuos ot deirt ikkuT
,tnemom elbissop tsrow eht
,ti devom t’ndah retto dlo eht yhw tuB
.ot dedeen yeht naht regnol tnemom a gnitatiseh rehtien
,yldetaeper deneppah s’ti gnitseretni s’ti tub
,ohw floWcaM boR dna ,xoFarakaS yb
?gniggarb hcum os retfa
ruf tsehc s’arakaS ni elzzum sih deirub ikkuT nehT
.ylniatrec ,ddo saw tI .enirhs A
.gnirewsna erofeb ecnelis ni emit gnol a rof
,kcab yaw eht no ssendekan rieht revoc ot derehtob t’ndah ikkuT dna arakaS taht deciton meht fo yna fI
,sbir sih tsniaga dnuop ot nageb traeh s’arakaS ,neddus a fo lla
.seidob dekan rieht htob delddaws htmraw eht
tnet s’ikkuT dehcaer yeht nehw won tlef eh noisufnoc eht ot rehtorb saw neht tlef arakaS noisufnoc ehT .sgnippord on
,delbmurg retto dlo ehT ”?won tahW“
”.doof gnihctac fo erus eb dluoc I ecalp eno eb d’ereht wonk d’I
.rae sih ni derepsihw ikkuT ".dal ,si ti erehT"
.esroh wen a gniniart redir denosaes a fo taht ekil snoitom eltneg dna luflliks s’retto eht ,demat saw taebtraeh s’arakaS
,ekal eulb thgirb A
tel reven eh ,stirips eht yB
,eno rof llordeb ruf reednier nommoc a
.xof eht nopu klub sih tser ot devom reven eh rof
.htaehs sih fo tuo gnikeep pitkcoc sih htiw thguac eb ot tnaw t’ndid llits eh
.hcum pu denepo yllaer reven ,gnitsaob
,evig dluow thgis eht yllufepoh neht
,devaw dna dehctaw yeht oS
.retfa tsul dluoc eno
,efil gnol s’retto eht revo pu tliub llA .xes fo ruodo
.tcnitsni yb ylerup hcuop s’retto eht tsniaga ,elzzum sih fo sedis eht ,skeehc sih gnisserp flesmih dnuof arakaS .psag ot deunitnoc eh ”,doog yrev ,dooG“
tsuj ton tuB“ .kcab dehgis ronoC
.nworf desuora-flah
mih desaeler smra kciht s’ikkuT sa ruf sih hguorht hsur ria dloc  tlef arakaS
,ynapmoc s’rehto hcae evah eW“
.tcnitsni luftsul yb nevird hcuot lamirp dna hguor eht
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
seye sih desolc arakaS
,sgel sih pu ti dellup
.dehsinav dah niorg s’ikkuT ezilaer ot tnemom a mih koot ti taht ecneirepxe eht ni tsol os saw eH
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf ygolohtna na
.dal ,eno yrt dluohs uoy ,hO“
.llew dekrow ti dnA
.xof eht nopu thgiew sih tser ot nageb eh dna
,gniht eno rof nraey straeh riehT
,hguoht gnorw ro decalpsim llac thgim wef a hcihw
kcen sih fo kcab eht ot enips sih fo esab eht morf ohce tlef xof eht taht duht llud a htiw neht dna
,nehT ”.daem naht retteB“
,etam sih dnuora mra gnorts a depparw aneyh ehT ”.tey
.erom rof tsriht mih edam taht yaw a ni elgnit evren elgnis yreve
.tcaf taht fo mih dnimer ot
.liat sih fo esab eht tsniaga rits gnihtemos tlef arakaS dna ,deknilb ikkuT ”.ecaf ym ni nikskcub ruoy dessot uoy erofeb thgir kool doog a tog I
?ti t’ndluohs ,hguoht
,dal ,kciuq ffo teg...“ ”?tahw derednoW“
.nihtiw rits gnihtemos tlef htob yeht ,tsal tA
,smra s’retto eht otni gnibmilc yb eciov sih dnuof arakaS ”,lleW“
.gniht eno s’ereht“
.ecalp otni kcab gnignirps hcnarb tneb a ekil eerf dellup kcoc sih dna
”.dal ,ecaf ruoy revo lla daerps em fo ffihw a ekat ot deen tsuj“
”?nuf evah uoy did“
,ruf rieht fo htob no dees fo llems tcnitsid eht deciton ro
tpels esle eno on
,tol a siht gnikil er’uoy ,mmM“
.rethgual fo surohc a dekovni hcihw kaeuqs lufitip
,uvval eht fo ssenkrad eht ni dehgis ikkuT ”,saw emiT“
,deffuh arakaS ”-esaelP“ ”…enim eganam ot nrael nac uoy neht ,siht ekat nac“
.tahw rettam on esimorp sih no doog ekam dluow eh dediced
,seidob s’rehtohcae tlef yeht nehT
ikkuT dna eh ekil nem taht sdnob euqinu eht dnatsrednu reven dluoc ohw nem erew yeht
.enog reven dah arakaS sdnuorg otni
,hgiht s’ikkuT tsniaga dnuorg ti erehw regae dna
drawrof detfihs spih s’ikkuT
,htmraw s’retto eht leef ton did eh ,teY
emaceb snoitom sih ,yllautneve
,yltnangidni ,sdap sih tsniaga debborht kcoc digir ehT "?ti si
dna mraw s’ikkuT fo noitasnes ehT
,emoh tniop eht evird ot fi sA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
ot detnaw tsuJ“ .dias dah retto eht ”,dal
,ti derreferp arakaS
.yalp ot detnaw tneserp ydobon eno dna
.daeh sih koohs arakaS
,ylthgils flesmih derewol ikkuT ”?uoy t’nera
,dnim ,eno ylno dna
.nwod ti evil retnuh roop taht
kcoc s’arakaS fo ecafrus eht decart mlap s’ikkuT ”,roirraw ruoy fI“
,neddus morf raf neeb dah srieht fo ycamitni sihT
.wols dna efas dna taf si ereh emaG
”?eno rehtona evah uoY“
".em pleH .eb ot tnaw I"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.eb syawla t’now I tuB“
.ylpeed delahni dna
.stlep ressel dna sessarg tfos fo elip eht pota deyalpsid ylduorp niksraeb a htiw evisserpmi etiuq dna owt rof hguone gib tsrif eht
,tnecs s’ikkuT etsat ot drawrof denael yllanif arakaS nehT
.lufssilb saw nwo sih tsniaga gnibbur htgnel elppus
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.rehtegot meht ekorts ot nageb eh
.llits og mih dniheb retto eht tlef arakaS
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
- snoitom tsetfiws dna skcart tsetniaf eht wollof ot erew yeht sa deniart - seye s’xof eht rof tub ,hcum t’nsaw tI
”…derednow ev’I semitemos oS
.seceip dna stib detrossa yal ereht
.spil s’arakaS ta gnikcil dna gnoht nikskcub sih gnitaemrep ,luos yrev sih
,pal ym ni pmur s’dal emosdnah a rof
,pitkcoc yhs sih dezarg pitregnif a emit hcae dna
,uoy ekil retnuh emosdnah a tnuom dluoc I“
.sgniggel edih dna htolchceerb derreferp syawla d’eH
.deksa dah arakaS ”?em gnillet uoy era yhw oS“
"…derapmoc yllaicepsE"
.elzzum s’xof eht nwod dna pu eglub eltbus eht dnuorg yltneg dna spih sih kcor ot nageb eh ,thguoht hcum tuohtiW
arakaS dna ikkuT
”.yaw siht retteb ti ekil I ebyam“
emit a fo dednimer saw eh dnA
.esrow hcum os tlef evah tsum ti
.ylrae emoh enog dah ohw
,ecalp a tog ev’uoy doog s’tI
.feiler fo hgis a ehtaerb htob dluoc yeht
,erom raeh ot detnaw yeht fi dnA .dias dah eh
.meht gnoma neeb reven dah arakaS
kaeps uoy fi nrael t’now uoY“
.ot drawrof kool ot noissap detaeh fo thgin a dah yeht tuB
,gnihtyna fi tuB .edurc
,ereht s’ti wonk uoY
,stsirw sih fo eno koot wap s’ikkuT nehT
.noitanalpxe eno neeb evah thgim ereht tub
eno siht piks esaelp
,yb dessap ti sa ti fo pit eht rof dehcaer eugnot siH
traeh kaew fo t’nsaw arakaS tuB .elbaraperrI
,daem deirt dah arakaS .deksa dah arakaS
.seirellag yrruFoS evitcepser rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,kcoc s’arakaS deppuc dnah rehto s’ikkuT
arakaS ,revewoh ,won roF
gnihtemos erew dleh gnieb ylerem fi sA
.seye nwo sih htiw nees dah ikkuT taht ,dnim kaew ron
.pmal wollat tilnu ,dloc a dna kaolc ytsum a depard saw hcihw revo
.keehc s’arakaS no ruf eht dekorts dna nwod dehcaer eh sa eciov sih ni nrecnoc eniuneg htiw won ,deksa eH
.siht nees dah eh emit tsrif eht t’nsaw siht
.skcoc rieht uoy dewohs ylgnilliw ohw elpoep ot ysetruoc nommoc wohs ot ton edur ylbirret neeb evah dluow ti
gniddeb niksraeb dedlof eht tsniaga tis ot kcab dils eH
tnetsisni dna tnulb gnihtemos
.derepsihw arakaS ”.eb dluoc tI“
.retto dlo eht rof pu dekcap dah redoog-od emos dna ,evom eht no gniog saw ebirt eht sselnu ffo nur dluoc ti taht ton
.derepsihw ronoC
”.em rof ton tsuj s’tI“
.eb ot desu eh tahw t’nsaw yllaer eH
.seramthgin sih ni eciov s’retto dlo eht raeh tsuM
.murd eht ni sgnivrac tuo ekam dluoc eh erows arakaS ,kaolc
evitcnitsid eht dna ksum larutan fo ,trid dna taews fo egalloc a
,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer
ylno fI .ylerab ylno fI
.ekil-esuom tsomla dna keem eciov sih ,derewsna arakaS ”,si tI“
thguoht ikkuT fi tub
tol a t’nsi hcihw
.sehsub eht ni seirrucs taht erah eht sa yhs sa kcoc sih dnif ot ylno
,niaga raen speerc enimaf reve fi oS
.elppin s’xof eht dnuof eugnot s’retto eht llit
.esnopser ni delkcuhc dna elims-flah a decrof arakaS .kcits a htiw sehsa eht gniborp
.uvval eht fo tuo dekcud eh sa htolcniol sih denetsafer arakaS  ".nekorb gnitteg fo regnad ni eno eht t'nsaw eh" ,yltsenoh
,kciuq eb ot dah yehT
.liat sih detfil dna ,dnuora denrut
,flesmih derewol eh sa ikkuT dias ”,teiuQ“
.ydob sih leef t’ndiD
etam a gnivah ot segatnavda erew erehT
,nikskcub thgit eht tsniaga hsup dna worg ot detrats yllanif hcihw ,kcoc sih delkcit erusaelp fo egniwt a sa
.flesmih rof ti koot dna yawa wap s’xof eht dehsurb retto eht
.nwad erofeb emit emos yltneg arakaS nekow dah ikkuT
,snoissessop s’retto dlo eht deips eh
.emarf nedoow s’uvvaL eht morf gnignah shtom yb netae-flah sehtolc dna ,srenroc eht ni tuoba nwerts stop yalC
,ebyam ,namahS eht ro stoor rof ereh pu emac sregarof spahreP
.eson s’xof eht fo pot no tser gnoht nikskcub eht fo klub eht gnittel
,retto fo llems ehT
pit eht no dnah a tup dah ikkuT tub
.ffulb ykcor peets a fo egde eht dnuora mih del retnuh retto eht sa
,litnu retfiws tog sekorts s’retto eht
,deb ot gnikat htrow saw eh
,htolcniol sih rednu edils wap a tlef arakaS ”…llits dluoc uoY“
.arakaS ,seigolopa yM“
,tfahs s’xof eht ssorca detrups dees s’retto ehT
.hguoht esimorp a saw esimorp A
…eb semitemos nac stluser eht
.tiperif eht fo edis etisoppo eht no ilevuK oN
”,mih evig I tahw si ti os dna ,sekil ronoC tahw si tI“
,stnemom wef a koot tI
,terces ym s’ecalp sihT
.erifnob tseggib eht naht rettoh denrub llits tsul s’ikkuT esuaceb tsael toN
.mih edisni saw retto dlo eht dna
.ereh saw ti wenk uoy erus ekam
desopsid ylralimis gnieb yrt ot hguone suoiruc erew ohw nem ro
,oicodaggarb detirips emos retfa ,emit tsaL
tnet eht dellif taht selam eht fo tnecs derahs eht nwod deplug eh sa devaeh tsehc s’retto eht
,oga gnol oot lla ton
,htaerb detiab htiw detiaw arakaS hcihw hguorht
”.netsil naht rehtar
rehtegot spil rieht desserp
,yeson dna edur raeppa ot gnitnaw tuohtiW
,nwod retnuh rehtona hsup ot ekil saw ti tahw wenk eH
.gnoht rehtael-kcub rehtona morf sehcni elzzum sih gnivael
,dab os ton s’tahT"
.yrovi denekcalb eht htaeneb ecalp otni kcab revoc eht dils
,ohw redle detcepser a fo yrotsih hcir a
.pota yal yeht sedih lamina enif eht ni seloh deppir swalc sih dna stsif otni delruc swap siH
,ecaf s’xof eht fo edis rehtie no seenk sih detnalp dna denruter neht
,kcab decnalg arakaS
,dedeen ikkuT noitamrifnoc eht lla saw don thgils ehT
.thgilerif eht ssorca s’arakaS tem seye s’ikkuT .depley yllanif sakajraH ”?lleW“
,rehtegot anuas eht traped ot edam
.ti noitnem ot tsrif eht eb ot detnaw meht fo enon neht
,nwo sih ot saw tnet s’ikkuT ralimis woh erawa ylneddus saw arakaS ”.no kcab nikskcub
.ruodo ylidob enivid dna sezeeuqs regae s’retto eht yb delffum eciov sih ,desufnoc elttil a derewsna eh ”,od I ,haeY …hu I“
,tnemom gnissap hcae htiW
,revewoh ,yrartnoc eht nO
,tsaehtron eht ot edir s'yad flah a kcabesroh no tuo tes yeht ,sraeps thgil fo eldnub llams a gniyrrac hcaE
,tsehc sih tsniaga ni deldarc sretnuh rehto ynam woh wenk-ylno-stirips htiw tneps ,sraey sih lla nI
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
”?tonk eht eit uoy nehw pih sih kaerb ot ton woh ,ekiL“
,niap tsomla saw tahw fo hsalf yratnemom a saw erehT
”?htolcniol eno evah ylno uoy oD“
pu gniwohs eb t'now ti meed d’I neht
.emit doog a dah uoy dalg m’I“
,tcilfnoc yeht nehw dnA
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,yot wen a htiw god deticxe na ekil gaw ot nageb liat siH
.emit doog ni llA
.ti swonk em tub retnuh on erus ytterp
,thgil on saw erehT
,ruf sih ro htuom sih etsat t’ndiD
,eciov dna seye sih ni eelg dliw a saw ereht tub
,wap-ni skcoc htob htiw ,neht dnA
,nem desopsid ylralimis teem dluoc yeht erehw
.ezeeuqs a keehc erab s’arakaS evag neht
,niaga wolg taht was arakaS .seye
,deerb ot erised ehT
.thginot rof tsael ta
edisni yletelpmoc gnimoc yb tsuj taht hguone llams saw tnet ehT
ton fi yllufhturt ,dias arakaS ",hO"
,selop tnet eht no gnuh ti erehw morf nwod gnihtemos dekculp dna denrut ikkuT sa swoble sih no depporp dehctaw
.noynac neddih ynit a saw
,ruf kcen s’arakaS ni ecaf sih deirub
.mih ediseb xof eht rof moor ekam ot
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,deyonna-flah a htiw xof eht ta derats eh sa eciov sih ni nrecnoc fo tnih a
.tnavelerri saw etsat tub
,emoh teg ot dedeen eH
,kcab sih no yal arakaS
.yks thgin eht ni decnad taht sthgil retniw eht lavir ot hguone thgirb llits tub ,won retniaf
.llordeb eht no mih ediseb nwod yltneg xof eht dellup
,ylidaetS ".siht ot"
.ti hguorht leef llits nac uoy ,eltneg dna esolc uoy sehctulc ti
”sthgiR gniggarB“   yojne esaelP
”?nam rehtona gnikaT
,meht htaeneb sniks lamina eht ta
,secalp evitcepser rieht demuser dah retto eht dna xof eht litnu ton tsael tA
a tuo tel eh dna
,daem fo niks rehtona rof llac ,mih yfsitas
,rellams saw rehto ehT
.keehc sih tsniaga hsurb wap s’ikkuT fo sserac tfos eht tlef neht dna
.shgiht regae sih neewteb teg ot kcab dellup retto eht dna
wol dehctip saw ,tnet rellams eht otni dils arakaS sa ,eciov eht ”,lleW“
.mih morf nrael ot tol a tog lla ev’uoy“
,emirp sih tsap retto dlo eht rof ,ylnO
,staog dliw fo kcolf a delwarps retaw eht ssorcA
deniamer s’ikkuT tub
,siht naht redrah eb dluohs tI
kcab yltneg ti dellup
,stops gnipeels owt erew erehT
,si tniop eht tuB
.sraef sih kcab dloh ot tliub dah eh reirrab eht ti htiw nekat dna detfihs ylerem dah dniw eht fi sa ,elbanialpxenu saw tI
mih htaeneb tfihs xof eht tlef ikkuT
.retal ro renoos wohs rieht teg dluow yeht os dna
,senob dlo sih ot gnulc taht sseniraew eht yawa desahc gnivah tnemeticxe eht
”.gnihtemos deen I
,deedni emag suoregnad a saw egdelwonk suoicerp hcus htiw enoemos tespu oT
,tsiaw sih dnuora mra ynob sih depparw dna xof eht dehcaorppa ikkuT elihw lla
,nwod flesmih tas dna kcab delffuhs eh oS
.retto eht denioj dna tiperif eht ot revo delffuhs eh
”.evrats t’nseod ebirt eht nehT
,ffurcs kcen sih fo edis eht no yltneg elbbin ot ecnahc a xof eht evag hcihw ,yawa decnalg retto eht ”,lleW“
.leef ereht gnieb edam ,ereht
.gniredloms erif eht tfel evah dluow I ,tseug a evah ot gniog saw I wenk I fI
,ilevuK gnikaw diova ot hguone tfos dna
.ecarbme did yeht neht dnA
,yad dab a tsuj t’nsaw ti wonk oT
,yletarepsed dekrab arakaS ”!tiaw ,tiaw ,tiaW“
,ylregae sraeps sih fo eno deppirg dah arakaS .egde s’retaw eht ta delbbarcs eseeg taf dna
.ni tuc ikkuT yraew a
.sretnuh rehto eht fo tnemtnioppasid eht ot hcum
.dnob ylurt ot emoc tsrif dah yeht erehw
.nem rehto gniddeb xof eht fo tcepsorp eht ta suolaej rehtar tog netfo ohw
.ruf s’rehtohcae fo tnecs eht peed dehtaerb
,rehtohcae morf skcor gnimaets dna erif eht ssorca
,noisserpxe s’roirraw eht daer ot krad
tuo ekam ot drah saw tI
neewteb yal ,llits rorrim
,ezag s’ikkuT dleh arakaS ”,kniht I“
oot saw tI ”.gniht fo dnik taht rof
,edis sih no yal won ohw
.resolc retto eht gnitivni ,tsrif ta ylwols
,xof eht sserac ot deunitnoc dna tas eh ,daetsnI
.ereht thgir llits saw ikkuT ,yhw
-Y“ .sthguoht suoixna
,moor eht dnuora pu tnew selkcuhc wef A  2 fo 2 traP
.hcnilf ot retnuh dlo eht desuac dna sredluohs s’ikkuT dezies xof ehT
”?uoy tnuom ot em tnaw llits uoy od ,nehT“
.deb remrof s’anaS nisuoc sih ylniatrec saw tahw
.yaw eht fo liated yreve eziromem ot erus edam dah arakaS ,kcab yaw eht llA
,ecalp a tog s’ebirt ruoy taht ,esoppus I ro
terces a peek ot esimorp a rof gniksa retnuh a ni ees thgim eno ekil
.noitaripsni dedeen eht ,llew
.feilebsid ni fi sa ,siht ta daeh sih dekcoc ikkuT ”!lla s’taht
s’rehto hcae otni derats yeht elihw lla
.noitcere s’retto eht ot ti dediug dna
,rehtael kcub devreserp-llew dna nrow fo ,elam desuora fo
”,thginot dloc elttil a pu dne thgim eW
.shgiht ot skcoc ot seilleb ot stsehc ot skcen morf
.neht ,trats ot arakaS ot pu saw ti ekil dekooL .ydaernu
ssenkrad eht nI .hguone saw ti
,kao wolloh fo eceip a morf edam murd dlo nA
,desu eb ot gnilliw dna ydaer
.redrah deggaw liat sih sa gnoht eht tsniaga eson sih gnisserp elihw ylteiuq denaom dna ,siht ta deffuh arakaS
.skeehc s’xof eht tsniaga tfahs sih dnirg ot drawrof desserp ,tnecs eht ot dednopser spih siH
,ti tfel dah eh erehw thgir yal retlehs s’ikkuT
.thgin digirf eht otni deraeppasid yltfiws dna sevlesmeht dnuora tlep reednier a depparw setamdeb eb-ot-noos owt eht
,erif eht ediseb dehcuorc eh sa dehgis retto eht
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
,stnalp rehtag ot yaw siht pu emac
,detsisni arakaS ”,os toN“ ”.lla ta
.doolb regae htiw mraw dna drah-flah
,saw tnecs s’ikkuT lufrednow woh gnitatsrednu on saw erehT
.rehtaeh hcir fo sknab kniht
,htlif dna dum ni selkna rieht ot pu dekac
.tsul s’xof eht dliuber ot dekrow lla ti
.emas eht saw doom eht tub
pu wohs t’now ti fI“
.mih pots kcabtes ylsaem eno tel t’ndluow xof eht erus saw eH
,srallod ruof evah gnidrocer siht fo sa dluow
,elbatpecca yltcefrep saw siht sa hcus ytidun lausac fi nevE
,htaerb peed a koot xof ehT
.won detcelloc erom ylraelc sthguoht sih ,deunitnoc eh
.seye s’arakaS otni peed dekool dah retto ehT
,yrtne rof yltnegru gnisserp
,sllih eht otni htron gninrut
.llordeb derahs rieht no ekawa gnittis aneyh a ees tsuj dluoc eh krad eht nI .ezorf xof ehT
.snoinapmoc rieht ot seirtnasaelp dereffo dna esor ikkuT dna
.reddalb rieht ytpme naht
,esruoc fo dlo ton ,retto eht