eekcus ym gnihctulc
.doog yllauqe erew mih morf dah I seeffoc fo stes owt txen eht tub
.mih ta kcab ylkcis delims tsuj nyliraM tub ,maS denihw
,meht tluaf yltcaxe t’naC
.elpoep rehto teem ot doog emos uoy od dluow ti ,sediseB“ .deooc nyliraM
saw ydobemos rehtehw
,taht no dnim fo ecaep emos dah I os
knalb denrut dnim ym oS  .tsael ta
,rehto hcae ta snoisserpxe gniwonk edam meht fo owt ehT
,hO .ti ot erehda yllautca dna drow efas a no deerga htob ev’uoy sselnu ton ,tihs tneloiv oN
emos sa mih gniyfitnedi ylbissop
.wolgretfa eht ni dezad elttil a tlef I taht ,yllufecrof os ,drah os emac I
”,flesruoy eb ot saw uoy morf detnaw I lla ;yrraH ,wonk uoY“
.sevlow su no deretnec ylegral erew
,roolf dnoces eht ot pu gnidael sriats eht pu ylregnig edorts I
gniht uhluhtC/diuqs/supotco eguh a was I sa degnirc I
,wonk t’ndid I srehto gniteem tuoba
yb hserf sgniht peek ot rehtegot sgniht wen gniyrt ot koot yllautneve eW .sknik
emos htiw raeb yklus eht noitnem ot toN
”?uoy t’ndid ,ti deyojne uoy tub ,si ti seY“
.margorP gnidaeR remmuS ruo sedulcnoc sihT
.goD fo tsohG no
?thgir ,smelborp rieht tuoba wonk ot rehto eht detnaw tnemtraped hcihw esuaceb
.maS dneirfyob ym tub eb ti dluohs ohw dnA
,emit txen ni enut tuB
!on snaem ti ,on yas enoyna fi ;ereh evah ew elur ylno ehT
dna skaerb hcnul ot xes timil ot hguone denilpicsid saw nyliraM tub
wonk uoy dluow woH
.ekawa peek ot yaw emos dnif ot dah I taht hguone gnirit ro ,gnirob
.daeh sih hguorht gnissap gniht latem
.pu gnithgil noisserpxe sih ,su sdrawot denrut lwoc a gniraew tab trohs A
.etaicerppa ot I neve
,yadirf dna ,yadsendew
”?tseb ruoy saw ohw nehT
dedda ylno ,edistuo decalp snikpmup gniwolg eht ot noitidda ni hcihw ,riaffa nairotciV eguh a saw ronam ehT
,sgnieb gnikool-yracs ot gniklat
tnereffid sa tey ,syaw ynam os ni ekila er’eW
.arbacapuhC eht esoohc uoy oS“
.ronam eht sdrawot gnitturts tuoba tes dna
.ereh elbissop erew srevossorc lauxes taht ylno
gninetsil rof uoy knahT   .stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
ni ekil ,wonk uoY
.sdnuob fo tuo era sdnuorg eseht ni erehwon ,dekcol t’nera srood eht sa gnol sA“
.thginot lwoh llahs srevol retsnom owT
,deipucco saw ytrap siht ta sklof rehto eht fi taht dediced I
”?tuoba ekops uoy relaed ssalc hgih eht htiw dneirf ssalc-hgih ruoy siht sI“ .maS ot denrut I
,elzzun evitaicerppa na reh evag maS
enizagam rrumhO# ni deraeppa tsrif ”flesruoY gnieB“
”!nuf emos evah og dna ,enoemos dnif ,dnuora klaW
”erew“ gniog fo sepytoerets eht nosaer emos
,tsom eht noitnetta deyojne tonk dna tfahs ym fo trap hcihw yltcaxe wenk eekcus yM
,ylknalb deksa I ”?tahw neewollaH“
rof dna ,lleps ro esruc a ot eud laref gnimoceb fo llac eht ot debmuccus d’ohw slaudividni niatrec fo ekops dnegeL
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.nirg yflow a htiw spil sih dekcil maS
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,yawa deddap meht fo owt eht tuB
,elpoep fo tol a wenk erus nreV
.dneirfyob ym pu dedne taht flow etuc eht tem
msagro tseb driht ym dah I .euqitsym eht ot sdda emutsoc ehT
,sisahpme ni epac dna sgniw sih deppalf nreV
.ylrae no tca rieht gnitteg saw enoemos gnitseggus
”.secaf s’rehto hcae gniees tuohtiw rehtona eno ta og a evah dna…“ .detcejretni I
.sevlesmeht eb ton ot detcepxe erew yeht esuaceb
erofeb tnemom feirb a rof dengila srats eht nehw ,ekulf a neeb evah syawla dluoc tI
,wodniw eht yb tiftuo emina rolias emos ni cennef a revo dehcnuh
htiw tnew llits uoy dna sraey eseht lla ,nreV ,ylsuoires tuB“ .maS diaS
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,gniog gniht doog a dah su fo eerht ehT
.pu deklaw taht elpuoc rehtona ot denrut nreV
”…gninnigeb tsuj ylno s’thgin eht ,wonk uoy dnA“ .deilper maS
redaelreehc a sa desserd em dekcuf
did tahW .gninetraehsid rehtar saw em htiw no ti
.won drah I saw ,nmaD
.flesym ronam eht erolpxe tsael ta dluoc I
.epytoerets elcatnet iatneh eht evol attoG
.ronam eht fo llah niam eht otni edorts I sa
.eno yb ffo dekcus tog neve uoy woN ?sretsnom ro snomed yb dekcuf gnitteG
klus a kcab tib I
.mih otni no-drah ym fo tohs retfa tohs gnidaolnu
saw maS taht derevocsid I ,ssecorp taht ni dna
,yteicos ruo ni stsixe llits noitaderP
.sedosipe neewollaH laiceps ruo fo tsrif eht rof ,erad uoy fi
.gniyalpelor rof hcum oS
.eno eht eb ot dah eh derugif I
.nyliraM htiw kool a degnahcxe I dna
.egap ruFikiW ro ytiniffAruF sih no
wam nomed ro selcatnet neve spahrep ,yssup dna ssa gnitteg yb dessap ev’I enoyreve fo suolaej saw I ,ylterceS
dna eeffoc rof tuo tnew I nehw saw laicos eb ot tog I emit ylno yM
”.od ot tuo gnituocs emos tog
gnittahc detrats ew woh saw taht dnA
.stneve eseht ta gnissim erew uoy tahw ees ot uoy rof doog
.sruoh eciffo retfa
.rehto ro retsnom pmaws
.seeffoc ym fo eno gnipperp atsirab a saw eh erehw ,kaerb krow a gnirud éfac a ni mih tem tsrif I
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif
.’esle gnihtemos‘ dias I ,sediseB
nac uoY .srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG dna ,yellaV tibbaR
?t’ndid I taht evah srehto
,yadnom yreve edosipe ykoops esiwrehto ro ,yrots tsohg
gnitteg ni detseretni demees eno on taht tcaf ehT
?ssa revo hself god dna flow rof
tiftuo siht erow I maS llet t’ndid I
,ot sdneirf ym dna maS htiw enog ev’I snoitnevnoc scimoc ro yalpsoc
.si neewollaH tahw wonk I“
.srieht fo ysatnaf emos lifluf ot tbuod on
”.htiw ffuts ,mu—kcus ot retteb eht llA“  .tab eht delims
.trosnoc sseripmaV ,suartS nyliraM retnE
.eciffo eht ni enola gnieb fo tol a tnaem ti oS
,did yeht sa sesion gnikcus ypruls
.wam ym otni ti gnippils erofeb tfahs sih delzzun I sa denaom maS
eno fo elor eht no ekat dluoc I yadot spahreP
.wam s’roivas ym otni trups retfa trups gnipmup
.rekihhctiH flowereW ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,floWisakiM yb
?tnaw ew reveohw kcuf dna
.gnidnats srehto ,detaes emos ,tuoba delgnim stseug eht fo emos ,ereH
,ti gniraew llits krow retfa maS liar ot tog netfo I sa
,tleb ym delkcubnu I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
gnihtemos fo snoitasnes delgnim eht dna
”?ffo skcor ruoy teg dna ,t’nera uoy esle gnihtemos eb ot dneterp uoy nac raey eht fo yad rehto tahW“
etirovaf rieht fo semutsoc ni pu sserd elpoep ,eve s’neewollaH nO“
,lausu naht erom rehto hcae gniees su dah emoh morf gnikroW
eht fo eno erew ew tcaf eht eb dluoc tI
neek taht lla t’nsaw I
.guh a htiw maS ta pu gnipmuj ,delaeuqs eh
?erew yeht dias yeht mohw
,sehcaorppa htnom eht fo dne eht sa erom htiw
,ysub detca dna dehsuh enoyreve ,roolf noitcudorp
.ssel on ,lrig naitaslA na htiw deb ni ,ib
snikpmup eht tsap su dael maS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
dna eciffo eht ni sdnuor ruoy edam dna tuo tnew uoy revenehW
wam kcils s’enoemos otni gnidils saw I taht niaga dna ecno gnihsiw
?thgir ,ereht enoyreve tnaem taht noisnetxe yb dna
”!ti edam uoy ,ymmaS“
dna erusserp gniylppa dna gnikcil eugnot dna htuom sih
,ot evord ew ytrap eht ta tsoh eht wenk eh dias maS tub
,elbidua cisum pop ro kcor fo eralb tneibma
ekil dednuos tahw edam meht fo owt ehT
.ereh rehtona eno ta og a evah dluoc
.egami eht etelpmoc ot rae thgir ym dniheb edocrab erutangis s’74A kni maS dah neve I .eb
”?ytrap xes a ti llac tsuj ew t’nod yhw oS“
,gnipmuht dna snaom raeh dluoc I hcihw ni nav a gnidulcni ,dekrap erew srac rehto eht erehw yawevird eht otni dellup I
rehtie saw mrif lanoitanitlum
gnieb dna retcarahc yna ,sohtym ro esrevinu revetahw ro ,levraM ,CD saw ti rehtehw rettam t’ndid tI
eht htiw ,nepo ylegral erew syawllah eht morf
,delaeuqs cennef ehT
,ereh enoyna wonk t’ndid I
,roolf dnoces eht dnuora tiucric a gnikam retfA
,wonk t’ndid I elpoep fo sdworc htiw
.em ekil tsuj flow a s’maS  floWisakiM yb
reve nac sa ciots sa ecaf ,eit der dna tius ym
.daeh em gnivig daeh s’arbacapuhC emos fo thgis thguac dna
.mih tuohtiw reven ,os neve dna
,floWisakiM yb ”flesruoY gnieB“
.erom ecno desuora em teg t’ndid esimorp taht fi ,nmaD
.retirw yranecrem flow a
llew oot od t’ndid I ,dnuos yam ti sa egnartS
.oot doog ytterp tlef nyliraM tub
,sih fo sdneirf erew gniteem pu dedne I elpoep rehto ylno ehT
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
gnirednow pleh t’ndluoc I dna
,neht boj eht ot wen saw maS
.yrassecen yletulosba saw ti sselnu uoy ot kaeps t’ndid elpoeP .elor emosenol a saw reganam a gnieB .boj yad ym ni reganam a sa dekrow I nehw yllaicepse
.mih dnuora yllacitamard gnisiar epac sih ,sgniw htob desiar nreV
,lla dna serutaerc kcap gnieb ,seitinummoc mrof ot seiceps tsrif
?ebyam ,nodrah A ?slliks laicoS
”.wonk uoy ,sepytoerets eht htiw gnola og attoG
eb dluow ti thguoht I os ,yug laicos a t’nerew uoy wenk I“ .maS dias
thguob syawla I esuaceb ,eno dias I
,gniog gniht nwo rieht gnivah maS dna nyliraM morf edisA
eno siht piks esaelp
.srae ym detnac I ”?spukooh nI ?sgnirehtag
,ffo em tog tahw yltcaxe wenk eH
.rovaf eht arbacapuhC eht nruter ot flowerew eht rof srennam doog saw ti tuB
.ti nopu ssik a gnidnal ,noitom tfiws a ni pu wap s’nyliraM deksihw nreV
dah I elihw nuf evah stsohg dna sluohg ,snomed rehto eht hctaw dluoc I erehw ynoclab a dnif neve ebyaM
no demrofni em peek ot deerga nyliraM dna maS tuB
,yerp ekil detaert gnieb ro msagro delgnim morf ti eb
.won yb em fo taht tcepxe stseug ym ,lleW“ ”’?eripmaV‘
.sevren ym gnimlac retaw gnilbbub fo dnuos eht ,doots niatnuof llams a ,ereH
,syaw etarapes nwo rieht gniog
.swap emal nwo ym fo daetsni
ni desserd ,kool namtiH 74 tnegA eht htiw
# ”.hcum oot flesruoy ot kcits uoY
I taht taht hguorht
,erom ssa dna kcoc dekil I
.tifeneb rieht rof ecaf thgiarts a tpek I dna ,degagnesid noos sdneirf owt ehT
dna stnaw ,sekil ,serised s’rehto hcae wenk ew woh saw tahT .detad dna
saw ti dna ,gniog pihsnoitaler nepo na dah ydaerla ew tuB
”.em rof tuo gnikool rof sknahT“ .detnap I
tnew I ?I rof sA
”?ytrap xes neewollaH a si yltcaxe tahw gniksa m’I
”,ecneirepxe eht etiuq s’tI
htmraw fo noitasnes eht dna ,edisa dellup gnieb wap ym tlef I
.tfahs ym gnipolevne ssenkcils
krow ot erow I tahw saw ti esuaceb ylniam
”.looc t’nerew ew fi uoy detivni evah reven dluow ymmaS ,gnilrad yrraH“  .deksa I
.em dna ronam eht evoba gninihs noom eht ta pu dekool I
.ebiv esuoH detnuaH eht ot
saw tsom ffo em tog tahW
.selkna ym dnuora gnirettalc stnap
.mhtyhr railimaf a ot ffo flesym gnikorts ,htaehs ym fo tuo yawflah ydaerla ,tfahs ym depsarg I
.evarg eht dnoyeb morf emoc ot dekool
.denihw I ”?em tuoba tahW“
.retsinab eht no delgae-daerps gniyl rehto ro ujiaK gnidnuos-eninimef emos ta og a gnivah raebartlU tsap
teem em evah ot tseb sih did tey ,elpoep htiw gnola teg t’ndid I wenk eH
”.evol ,tnemele yalpelor dna semutsoc eht fo esuaceB“ .deksa I
.ni daol sih welb eh sa gniraor
,kcul em thguorb tI .yawyna
tnahcnep a htiw bojtun yzarc emos t’nerew yeht fi wonk uoy od woH
I dna nyliraM ,em esucxe ll’uoy fi ,woN“ .dias maS
.eson ym no regnif a gnicalp yb em decnelis arbacapuhC eht ,revewoh ,drow rehtona rettu dluoc I erofeB
?yrraH dlo gnirob htiw kcits ot stnaw ohw esuaceb
,noom eht ta delwoh I sa pu daeh ym gniworht ym dah wen os tey dna ,railimaf os
ynapmoc em gnipeek won neve ,sllab ym delzzun eh sa spil sih dekcil eH
”.loohcs hgih ni kcab
.gnissim saw I ffuts eht lla tuoba gnikniht
.ylwols dias maS ”…sretcarahc
”?taht htiw yako htob er’uoY
.rehto ro retsnom emos htiw emit doog a gnivah fo daetsni
eht pu nrut ew ,tahw oS“
a fo reganam a gnieB .owt
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
”.thginot emit taerg a dah uoy taht si ,srettam ylurt tahw tuB“
.oot smitciv eht gnoma tnuoc yllanoisacco srotaderp dna
srehto htiw gnuws meht fo owt eht tcaf a rof wenk I
,egde eht ot resolc dna resolc gnitserc flesym tlef I sa taorht ym ni detpure lworg a fo sgninnigeb ehT
,seloh ’srehto hcae ta og a gnivah sretsnom dna snomed fo segami
,won nodrah a dah yletinifed I
”flesruoY gnieB“ saw sihT
.sserP terreF deR yb
,rorroh a tcepxE
”.yrutnec a fo bojwolb eht teg ot dalg m’I ,haeY“
gnitadimitni saw ti tub ,seivom rorroh ot emac ti nehw pmiw a flesym redisnoc t’ndluow I
”.os yas yam I fi ,era uoy ydal enif tsom a dna ,nyliraM dna yrraH ,ronam ym ot emocleW“ .snoitcudortni
.eb dluoc slaudividni owt yna sa
.gnihctaw deyojne maS
”?tcepxe ot tahw uoy dlot maS ti ekat I“
.taht em gnillac reh ot desu teg t’ndluoc llits I ,won raey a tuoba rof rehtegot gnivil su etipseD .ni tuc nyliraM
.wolg cinomed ,mraw a htiw mih gnitteuohlis edistuo thgil eht
.nihtiw morf gnitpure slworg dna spmuht ,slrans htiw desolc erew emos tub
ronam eht ni tops teiuq a dnif ylerab dluoc I tcaf eht yb decnedive sa
tlef em dnuora elpoep eht dna
”flesruoY gnieB“   yojne esaelP
noremaC hpesoJ nehw
.thgilnoom daorb ni tuo tsaeb renni ym gnittel
.ecnarebuxe ym ot ssentiw sa noom eht dah I ,emit siht ylnO
.did ehs sa spil reh gnikcil nyliraM
esoht fo eno gnidnetta ekil tsomla saw tI .nwo ym fo nuf
,eruS .mrof elamef eht ot esrevda
.dnuora gnignah stab dna slluks gniwolg htiw ,til ylmid saw tI
.dnim ym hguorht gnihsalf esle tahw swonk ohw dna selcatnet
,gnizilaicos naht rehtar sevlesmeht ot tpek sreganam rehto eht nevE
.emoh tog I nehw gniees ot drawrof dekool I ohw s’eH
taht em rof yllaiceps edam saw ti ekil tsuj ,thgir os
.potpal reh no rehto ro tnemngissa emos deldnah ehs sa noitasrevnoc ruo ta rae na dekcilf ylerem nyliraM .dehsinif maS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
?tseb drihT“  .dias nyliraM
.saw draytruoc eht erehw ,seiceps tnereffid fo sepahs eht otni devrac
.gnikcuf nyliraM dna em dehctaw eh revenehw tlef maS tahw saw tog I llirht elttil taht fi
.evisulcxe t’nerew ew tub
.seiceps rehto yna naht erom ”sevlowerew“ sa deyartrop yllausu erew dezarc gniog klof tub
kcab sih no senips eht
,em rof ereht saw eh ,tuo krow t’ndid taht nehW .srehto
,tsael yrev eht ta ro ,sesserdda
.daeh eht dniheb drah
”.moor gnidaer eht ni dnuora dessap gnieb deew emos s’ereht ,yaw eht yb
.sregnarts fo aes a ni enola os tlef I sa
.gnitacinrof ro gnizilaicos rehtie rof desu ecaps elbaliava yreve htiw ,ereh neve
.xim eht ni nworht
,semutsoc ruo otni tog su fo eerht ehT
srehcaelb eht rednu
.spukooh modnar dootsrednu etiuq reven I .oot
,htiw rac a ni gnikcuf
,esirprus ni nwod dekool I
”?kniht uoy t’nod ,gnittif fo dniK
t’nsaw I dezilaer
erew yeht elpoep fo srebmun etalp rac
,yawa ffup dna ffuh mih dehctaw I sa ezorf I
.emas eht t’nia tI“
neewollaH a ot og ot ekil dluow I fi deksa maS nehw
.secalp thgir eht lla ni hteet
,rehto hcae gnisirprus yllauxes
.emosenol ym no saw siht ekil stneve ta ffo teg reve dluoc I yaw ylno eht spahreP
?yad rehto yna ,mrE“ dehsinif ehs
.doog kcus eh did ,nmaD
,noitisop gnittis a otni deppord I
”.wonk uoy ,gnihton rof ”srekcus-floW“ sarbacapuhC llac t’nod yeht ,yeH“
rof hguone gnizilatnat saw tiftuo rehtael gnittif-mrof reh htaeneb mrof reh ,won nevE
yrassecen eht edam maS sa
.puteg yracs rieht ni evisserppo
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
?yas ot ereht s’tahw ,lleW“  .tuo ekops I
”.sliated eht no erab elttil a saw eH“
.ssel on ,raey eht fo yad tseiracs eht no ,ytrap xes
taht esoht yllaicepse
,thgilb-xes eht htiw desruc
gnidael smoor eht ot srood ehT
,satsirab suoiverp eht naht retteb hcum os detsat eeffoc ym nehw saw ti tub
.draytruoc teiuq a gnikoolrevo ynoclab a dnuof yllanif I