.edanomel ekil eniw etihw knard dna sgnik ekil eta sevlow htoB
.nibac siht ni emoh ta gnileef mih fo ngis a eb dluow elbatrofmoc flesmih ekam oT
.roolf dnoces eht no smoordeb eht dehcaer dna
.stigid sih neewteb yltneg elzzum s’velteD gnidloh
.niht saw eciov s’velteD ”.tcudnoc
mih ekat dna sesroh owt dna part esroh a hcteF“
.don llams a neht
edis sih no wap kcalb gnorts tahT
.elttab lanretni na thguof velteD
.rebos dloc-enots eb ot deraeppa llits dna tsom eht knard ohw
.regna sih hguorht rewolf ot nageb taht ynapmoc rof gninraey eht gnithgif
,lohocla ot ecnatsiser s’nafetS yb desirprus saw eH
.tekcop s’tsev sih morf hctaw tekcop nedlog a tuo dellup eH
.gnihcuot ylraen erew selzzum rieht litnu meht neewteb ecnatsid llams eht desolc dna llew sa pu esor nafetS
.pis egral a gnikat erofeb rouqil gnorts eht ta pu gniralf slirtson krad sih
”?joviliM retsiM ,erus uoy erA“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,won evael ym ekat llahs I ...I“
,yteicos yna ekil taht rebmemer tsum ew
”,sseug I ,dlo emaS“ ”?ajidiL s’woH“
,neppah dluow siht detcepsus velteD hguoht nevE
.mih dniheb sriahc tevlev gnitpmet eht erongi ot gniyrt ,ecalperif eht delcric eh sa snoitpo sih deredisnoc eH .MP 21:01
.ylsselmrah nekorb eb tonnac yehT
”!yletaidemmi em morf yawa flow siht teg ,renreW“
tliub era sllaw esoht
.loohcs hgih ecnis taht ekil neeb syawla dah tI
.demoolb ssenisub dna
esoht ni ,os nevE
.nafetS ot ti desiar dna
.seye s’rehto hcae ni gnirats sevlesmeht dnuof yeht dna rethgual decalper yllautneve ecneliS
.rehtona hcae tsniaga desserp ruf kcalb dna nat
.laem eht tser ot noos oot yawa meht tnes eH
.elbat eht rednu laed lanoisacco na dna ycamolpid
,deggurhs dna flow nat eht ta dekool ylerem nafetS
.erom rof deggeb velteD
?hcum os deveihca dah yeht taht gnisirprus os ti saw
.elims tub pleh t’ndluoc velteD
”.delttes si ti nehT“
,mih nopu nwod gnisserp ydob s’nafetS tlef
,gnorts dna egral erew sdnah siH
”.thgir er’uoy kniht I“
.swap owt no yats ot yletarepsed deirt eh dna
,ti tuoba thguoht eh fI
deregnil swap gnorts siH
,etsat tsrif eht retfa yspit tlef dna
.ytlayor ot seit tnatsid htiw seilimaf flow denwoner fo srieh dednim-ekil owt
,ecalperif eht morf yawa spets wef a kcartaoc eht ot nrut ot detrats velteD
,ytissecen fo tuo deirram eW .t’nod uoy ,oN“
nac uoY ..xofnogarD reppaD eht
.ylmlac deddon flow kcalb ehT
.dniw gnilwoh eht dna
,erofeb naht resolc
stseug tsal ehT .ecalperif gnilkcarc eht fo tnorf ni ylerusiel dellorts eh sa swodniw eht tsniaga gnilttar wons dna eci ,nibac nedoow suoiruxul eht edistuo gnilwoh dniw eht draeh joviliM velteD .denesrow dah mrots eht tub
,erif gniyd eht otnu dekcol ezag sih dna esacriats eht ot denrut kcab sih htiw nevE
,smra ywenis ,mraw
,krad eht tsniaga yllufituaeb detsartnoc
.swalc sih htiw ti ni serugif gniward
”?rof tsaot ew dluohs tahW“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.rehto hcae tsniaga gnidils dna gnipsar seugnot esruoc gnol rieht ,reideen
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.yletanoitceffa ruf s’rehto hcae gniffur
...hhhS“ .daeh s’velteD dniheb
,gnireffus eht taht dnA .meht tliub taht
.rood raja eht ot tnew eH
...neht dna ,doog gnileef saw eh emussa dluow nafetS
.esirprus htiw mih deye dna yletaidemmi mih desaeler ohw
.thgiewretnuoc s’rehto hcae
,yaw eht lla gnihgual dna seviw rieht tuoba gnipissog
.gnola gniddon ,flow nat eht deilper ”,saw ti ,seY“
.mrots eht ni eb rehtar dluow eh
eno siht piks esaelp
redluohs sih otnu daeh s’velteD dehsup wap tfel siH ”.og tel tsuJ“
”,ekatsim a saw su fo owt eht neewteb emit tsal deneppah tahW“
.sisab eman tsrif a no ton er’uoY
.deddon velteD ”.ylecin dleh ti tub
,velteD ta gniralg ,nafetS delbmurg
,rae sih otni derepsihw tnuoc eht ”,og tel tsuJ
,ytilibarenluv fo dnik ralucitrap a detcelfer ezag s’nafetS
,pu teg ot deirt eh sa velteD detsetorp ”,knurd ton m’I“
”,deb ot og ot emit s’ti kniht I“
.eno rekrad s’velteD gnidloh dna
,ecnats sih denethgiarts eH
,rehguor saw hcihw ,ssik dnoces eht ot on yas t’ndid eH
.ecalperif eht dna esacriats eht fo thgir eht ot ,nibac eht fo tnorf eht ni nehctik eht ot denrut tnuoc ehT
.kaerc deb eht gnikam
.ylper ot sdnoces wef a koot velteD
.hsif ecin yrev A“
;flesmih gnilkaew on saw eh wenk velteD .daeh egral
.yliratnemom pu deralf semalf eht
.smoor rieht rof tfel dah stnavres eht retfa gnol
”,tnuoC ,reporpmi si sihT“
.ssalg eno evres ot detrats nafetS sa velteD deksa
sriats eht dednecsa ylluferac dna ylwols yehT
.ruf sih rednu denrub skeehc s’velteD
,swap rieht ni ydnarb eht dleh yeht sa ecalperif eht fo semalf egnaro-peed eht devresbo sevlow htoB
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,dessorc serats rieht sA
:yltneg dias eh nehT .velteD thguoht
”?sevlesruo eb tsuj ew t’nac yhW
.noinapmoc sih fo ydob gnorts eht tsniaga gninael neht
,moor ytpme eht ta demaercs eh ”!renreW“
,derettum dna mih morf yawa seye tnereffidni sih denrut tnuoc ehT
.esirprus dlim ni worbeye yhsub a desiar ohw ,reirret eht neht
”!efiw ruoy fo hctib taht ot nruter dna daeha oG !neht eniF“
*  .ecrovid a rof enilednA deksa nafetS yad emas tahT
.tnemom a rof ezorf dna bonkrood eht koot nafetS
dloc eht htiw dna
stnavres god fo srettap dna skaerc tnatsid emac ereht sdnoces wef yrevE
,dnekeew taht dellacer velteD .seviw rieht htiw snoisnet ot del yllautneve emoh morf yawa sevil ysub rieht tuB
.tibbar_doowtfird@
.resolc denael eh sa denediw elims ykeehc s’nafetS
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daeR
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,rae nat a otni derepsihw nafetS ”?seY“
.eniw fo sessalg ynam fo ecneulfni eht rednu neve
.elbat eht gniraelc dna ,srood gninepo ,gniklaw
.thgis fo tuo tsuj deremmis llits regna sih tub ,denetfos dah eciov siH ”.dnatsrednu I“
dna nips dlrow eht tlef
,gnicar saw traeh s'velteD .rae tcere dna
”!evaheb ot woh ,od ot tahw su llet srehto tel ot tsuj raf siht emoc t’ndid eW“ .taps nafetS
.ssalg ytpme eht otni
,rewar hcum os
,ecnelis gnol ylralucitrap a retfa tnuoc eht detseggus
ekil taorht s’tnuoc eht morf yliratnulovni detarebrever lworg wol A
.ecarbme lufecrof eht ot ydob sih rednerrus ot noitatpmet eht detsiser eh sa ylesuforp gnitaews sdap wap
,od ot tahw erusnU
,ti detnemgua dah yeht
nuS eht dna tsiM eht neewteB“ yrots trohs sih ,yltneceR
.flow nat eht rof wapdnah a tuo dleh eh sa elkcuhc evarg a tuo tel nafetS ”.yspit tsuJ“
noinapmoc sih detalume velteD
wapdnah eno ni ydnarb fo elttob deneponu na gnidloh
,ecalperif eht fo tnorf ni thgin taht gnirebmemeR
,derepsihw eh ”,em wollA“
.denrub taorht sih sa dekaorc velteD ”,htoomS“
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.efil sih ni emit tsrif eht rof
”!god yzal uoy pu teG !renreW“
.deniamer srebme dna sehsa naht erom gnihton litnu erif gniyd eht derimda eh
yttup ot denrut sgel sih sa ydob sih evael ot demees htgnerts lla tub
.gnitirw dna gnidaer rof noissap a htiw tibbar a
;ylediw delims eH
,nafetS morf hgis gnol A
.renreW dna nafetS fo esirprus eht ot ,velteD dias
”.flesruoy ot eil t’noD“
”?kniht uoy od tahW“
etilop dna wol velteD ,duol nafetS
,rood dlo na fo gnikaerc eht draeh eh nehw
,tnatnuocca detsurt sih sa egrahc ni velteD tup eh
”,joviliM dneirf ,elbat eht ta yadot teiuq erew uoY“
”.rewueiD tnuoC ,seY“ ”.mih htiw oG“
,edis sih yb emac nafetS nehw evom t’ndid eH
,nohtaram a nur dah eh fi sa gnitnap saw flow nat ehT
.sriahc tevlev owt eht neewteb elbat a no elttob dna sessalg eht dial nafetS
.niarb sih otni yltcerid
;thgif lufrednow a retfa gnihsif fo yad dnoces eht fo dne eht ta ti thguac dah eH
,deb tfos eht no nwod dehsup saw eh nehw on yas t’ndid eH
.rehtegot deknilc latsyrc enif ehT ”.dneirf ,sreehC“
nac uoY .sserP syoB tsoL yb
”...dna sseflow doog a s’ehS“
,ylmrif edis s’velteD debbarg wapdnah thgir siH
,citsilaer dna lanoitar
,flow rehto eht ot resolc denael eH
.tsev sih hguorht ruf sih dekcirp yeht nehw hself sih hguorht yticirtcele gnidnes swalc prahs
,nelarD yb uoy rof daer ,doowtfirD yb
,ylsuoixna mih ta dekool nafetS elihw ,sselhceeps saw eh etunim elohw a tsomla roF
.tluaf a ot lamrof
:tuo derettum neht velteD
.pu rehgih evom ylwols ot detrats taht walc a htiw hgiht gnorts eht no selcric elttil gnicart ,delims nafetS
.dneirf sih fo seye eht gniteem
:smsirennam esoht wenk velteD
,emit tsrif eht rof nekat gnieb retfa dnA
?ydaerla etal os ti saW
.rehtegot gnibbur skeehc rieht ,ylthgit rehto hcae gnicarbme erew sevlow htob litnu
.daeh sih naht retsaf syawla saw htuom siH
,gnipoohw dna gnireehc nibac eht ot denruter mih dna nafetS
,trihs sih pu dellup dna tsev s’tnatnuocca eht denottubnu nafetS nehw on yas t’ndid eH
”?rewueiD tnuoC ,ti si tahW“
,htmraw htiw egnuol yzoc eht gnillif
.llew yllufrednow oS
.diuqil rebma eht ta ylevisnep nwod derats tnuoc ehT ”.htooms ...seY“
.noitatcepxe ni gnilims ,dneirf sih ot denrut nafetS
.sllaw nedoow kciht eht hguorht draeh eb ot gnipoh
.tsehc dna kcen sih revo gnihsaw shtaerb toh
.tneserp eht ot kcab velteD thguorb kcolc esacgnol a morf semihc nevelE
,pans dluow elop taht thguoht I“
,rednerrus ot eb dluow ti ysae woh mih gnillet
.retaw htiw nwod ti hsaw ot dah yeht
.oga ruoh na revo
.seye noom-lluf sih htiw gnidaelp tsomla
keehc s’nafetS tsniaga gnitnap flesmih draeh eh litnu gnihtaerb saw eh drah dna tsaf woh ezilaer t’ndid eH
.eci eht ni eloh eht hguorht tif t’ndid tsomla ti
.samora etaciled fo dairym a dna lohocla eht gnizilitalov
nafetS fo gnihtaerb yrgna ,yvaeh eht erew moor eht ni sdnuos ylno eht sdnoces emos roF
.elbissop sa nafetS morf yawa raf sa eb ot detnaw eh
.remaerd evislupmi eht
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.rehto eht ni sessalg latsyrc devrac owt dna
.meht neewteb elbat eht no erawssalg eht rof tuo hcaer ylbatrofmoc dluoc selam eht os ,rehto hcae ot esolc ylriaf erew sriahc htoB
,tuons evitisnes sih ot ssalg eht esiar ot tsrif eht saw nafetS
bew eht no seirots erom dnif
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mih dniheb dnats ot tnew dna mih derongi tnuoC eht tub
,seye nedlog esoht otni peed derats eh ,daetsnI
.kcab dehcnuh dna sgar emitdeb sih revo depard
.kcaba nekat saw velteD
,velteD gnittis eht ot txen tas dna deb eht ot revo tnew
.edaçaf lanoitar dna looc sih ot denruter yltsom dah velteD
”.velteD ,yaw emas eht leef uoy wonk I
.mih nopu ria lager a gniwotseb dna tsev krad
,elbat eht no skaets ekip detsaor erew ereht nooS
”.klat etairporppani s’tahT .daeh ruoy looc ot deen uoy kniht I“
.deddon velteD .renreW deksa
.thgilwol eht ni deremmihs ti kcalb os saw ruf s'tnuoc flow ehT
”.elop enif a s’tI“
.sevil s’elpoep fo
.eugnot sih ffo gnippils eman tsrif s’tnuoc eht ,deksa eh
.saw nafetS gnikool-doog woh dezilaer velteD emit tsrif eht saw tI
pu em ekaw ot srehto eht lleT
,emoh gninruter retfa nooS
:eciov dekcarc sih ni yltneg dias yllautneve renreW
.ees ot detcepxe reven
”eriF dna ydnarB“   yojne esaelP
.erif eht otni derats dna yliratnemom deppots velteD
”.taoc ruoy no tup dluohs uoy kniht I
stsaeB fo eripmE ygolohtna noitcifonex eht ni dehsilbup saw
.tnemredliweb yb decalper noitangidni sih ,kcab decniw velteD
sllaw nosirp eht nwod raet ot si ti sa ,yrassecen
”.neht sreehc ,lleW“
.ylnrobbuts detsiser rehto eht elihw
.selcsum gniglub gnisacwohs ,pu dellor erew seveels etihw siH
.deniamer semalf gnivrats wef a naht erom gnihton erehw ,ecalperif eht ot kcab denrut ylwols tnuoc ehT
.nwod tas yllanif tnatnuocca ehT
on yas t’ndid eH
wapdnah tfel sih detser nafetS sa ,hself sih gnizeeuqs
”.enoyreve rof retteb ...si tI“
”,tnuoC ,worromot uoy eeS“
:yltnahpmuirt dias dna sredluohs sih desiar neht
”?velteD ,eman tsrif ym yb em dellac uoy emit tsal eht saw nehW“
.nafetS morf elims
,wap kcalb eht koot velteD ”.neht no emoC“
,ylwols dnuora denrut neht eH
.dloc gnitteg s’ti dna wol si erif ehT“
,sriahc tevlev eseht ni ecalperif emas siht yb tas neht sevlow ehT
.saw ti ohw wenk velteD
.kcohs a sa emac llits swen eht
.deddon reirret ehT ”.enog s’eh retfa
tnemetats suolucidir A
deedni dna ,elbadnatsrednu sA
,tnellecxe neeb dah laem ehT  doowtfirD yb
margeleT no egassem a mih dnes
.ylhsrah nafetS detpurretni ”?reh evol uoy oD“
.velteD ta kcab dekool neht ,ydnarb fo pis rehtona koot eH ”.won eerf m’I
”.erom rof gniggeb erew uoY“ .delbmum eh
”.evol ...ytrebil ,efiL“
,ajidiL htiw gnithgif saw eH
.og ll’yeht nooS
,mlac dna suoituac saw velteD ,elihwnaeM
.seye krad sih ffo gnitcelfer thgileldnac eht
.seye sih htiw flow kcalb eht gniwollof
tfel dah
,yteicos evitamronoreteh fo
:derettum dna taorht sih deraelc velteD ,yllautnevE
,nafetS ta erats gninoitseuq a werht velteD .tnuoc eht derettum ”,snalp fo egnahc
.taht devorp tsev sih fo cirbaf eht tsniaga specib dna slarotcep sih fo eniltuo eht
:ylesraoh derepsihw dna
.daeh sih gnikahs ,yldaorb gnilims ,yawa denrut tnuoc ehT
,liat s’tnatnuocca eht htiw gniyalp saw ti litnu
”.pots ll’I dna on yas tsuJ“
.dehsinotsa saw velteD
.taht tnaw t’nod I .enola eb ll’ew nooS
.tsetorp fo drow a tuohtiw sretrauq s’tnavres eht otni tnew neht
”.joviliM dneirf ,deb ni tcudnoc reporp rof hcum erac t’ndid uoY“
”.joviliM dneirf ,worromot uoy ees ,lleW“
.sdnoces wef a ,niaga ecneliS
:ylmlac dias dna ,sredluohs sih no pirg sih desaeler nafetS
,rood eht desolc ohw nafetS saw ti tuB
,spets detanidroocnu htiw gniwolloF
.eerf uoy tes I .loof uoy ,taht yas erad uoy t’noD“ .rednuht gniraen
,selcsum sih dezeeuqs yeht nehw gnihtaerb deppots velteD dna
.riahc s’nafetS revo gnirewot
.eciov sih dnif dna wollaws ot dnoces a dedeen velteD
,god.ecioveht ta
”.klat su tel dna nwod tis esaelP“
,tnedifnoc raeppa ot stekcop sih ni swapdnah sih tup
”?nafetS ,hguorht siht thguoht uoy evaH“
.llew rehto hcae detnemilpmoc yehT
”.dooG“ ”.lliw ti spahreP“
.sih neeb dah tluaf eht wenk eh hguoht
,moor s’velteD ot rood eht denepo nafetS
.spil sih delruc ylerab velteD
.gninnirg ,mih ot kcab denrut flow kcalb ehT
,hgis gnol a htiw riahc sih no nwod tas eH
.esuap trohs A ”.elbissopmi
,retfins dnoces eht ni ydnarb ruop ot dedeecorp tnuoc ehT
;doowenip gninrub fo tnecs tnasaelp eht dna thgil
hguoht ,etsat a dah stnavres eht neve
,regnorts hcum os saw nafetS morf gnitaidar arua eht ,teY
,pu gnidnats erofeb taorht sih deraelc nafetS
”.ekip lufituaeb a saw tI“
.yaled a no skrow lohocla wenk eh hguoht neve
;erif gniyd eht otni ti werht dna ssalg sih koot eH
,moor eht fo ssenkrad eht ni detlem ydob kcalb siH
.sredluohs s’velteD dnuora taoc eht gnipparw erofeb
,ylyrd tnatnuocca eht dias ”,oN“
.spil krad sih no yltneg mih dessik dna elzzum sih detfil nafetS nehw ,retal sdnoces wef a on yas t’ndid velteD
”!oN“ .sbmil sih ni htgnerts eht gniniager
taht egral os saw hsif ehT
.dnim yzah sih hguorht tnatnuocca eht dekaorc ”...I“
detcepxenu na neeb s’erehT“
.pihsdneirf esolc rieht dnoyeb tnew taht gnihtemos
.sterger on evah I“
.neeb dah eh lanoitarri dna lanoitome woh dezilaer eh nehw seye sih ni gniraeppa emahs thgils
.hgiht sih no detser wapdnah a sa depsag neht
nwod meht raet ohw seno eht ton si ti taht
,ezag sih derewol nafetS
”!dratsab uoy ,em fo egatnavda koot uoy dna knurd saw I“
.sgnaf sih gnirab ,tuo taps eh ”,neht eniF“
.edis sih yb ti no gnittis erofeb deb dezis-gnik eht ot mih dediug
”.oot thgif suolevraM
,ruf nat trohs eht gnola stigid sih nar neht
.ylwols gniklaw nageb nafetS sa redluohs s’rehto hcae dnuora smra rieht depparw yehT
.pop tnahpmuirt a gnicudorp
,rehtegot pu nworg dah yehT .ti wenk eh dna
,sevlow eht ot ylwols delffuhs eh sa denway eh
.retaw ekil rouqil evisnepxe eht nwod dekcuhc dna ydnarb gniniamer s’velteD rof tuo dehcaer
.sllaw eht tliub ohw
,sreep degelivirp rieht fo tsom ekil senutrof 'seilimaf rieht gnirednauqs fo daetsnI
,doowtfirD yb ”eriF dna ydnarB“
snoitatpmet teews gnirepsihw saw tnuoc eht fi sa saw tI
”.siht tnaw uoy wonk I“
”!ssenetairporppa htiw lleh oT“
tey evissergga na mih evag swalc prahs sih elihw
.ajidiL efiw sih htiw ecaep edam velteD
,kcab sih ot dellevart
,ylthgils ti gnimraw
.riahc sih morf esor eh sa sgnaf etihw-yrovi gniwohs elims eltneg a
wap kaew a ni ssalg dellif-ylsuoreneg sih koot velteD ,elims a gnicroF
.kcar eht ot mih tsap ylksirb gniklaw
noiger eht ni mrif laicnanif tsegral eht thguob rewueiD tnuoC nehW
rehtegot seidob rieht desserp eh sa ,tnatnuocca eht morf pley desirprus a gnicudorp
tsev nwod-nrow a ni dehtolc saw dna eldnac til a dleh eH
velteD taht gnihtemos
taoc deroloc-eznorb nwo sih gniraew retal sdnoces wef a denruter tnuoC ehT
.thgindoog yas dna yawa denrut ev’dluohs eH
.rennid rof doc detlas naht tnereffid gnihtemos yllanif
,muirbiliuqe ni metsys a erew yehT
,erif eht fo wolg egnaro eht ni dlog denrut ruf nat siH
.seye ypeels sih dnuora dna revo gnidacsac ruf gniyarg ,gnol htiw reirret hsirI dlo na delffuhs tuo dna ,ylwols nepo dekaerc esacriats eht dna nehctik eht neewteb rood llams A
.yawa tnew ecnavda s’nafetS fo kcohs laitini eht sa raelc ot detrats dnim sih revo gof eht ,os nevE
.ecalperif eht evoba ekip detnuom eht ta pu dekool dna sthguoht esoht deraelc velteD
.taorht sih ni tonk a tlef yltnatsni ohw ,velteD ot dekcilf seye nedlog siH
,ssalg eht gnidloh llits ,riahc sih ni repeed gninaeL
.velteD fo thgir eht ta riahc eht no nwod tas eH ”.hsiw uoy sA“
.noissucsid detaeh a ni saw eh revenehw snoitome emos esaeler ot meht desu nafetS
.esnopser ni yllufemahs denihw ohw
.ffuts egairram taht ,tcartnoc laicos etelosbo na naht erom gnihton s’tI
.ylmlac renreW dias
,etunim a rof ecnelis ni deniamer sevlow owt eht sa sllaw nedoow ydruts eht no decnad thgileldnac gnirekcilf ehT
,thgindim tsap erif eht yb rehtegot deyats yehT
”,sretrauq s’tnavres eht ni peels lliw I“  ”.esruoc fO“
.yaw emas eht leef seviw ruO“
,deppop dna dekcarc tI
”.syawyna ti gnisu eb t’now I
,htmraw rof wodniw eht dna deb eht neewteb evots nori-tsac eht dekots ydaerla dah stnavres ehT
.rood eht ot resolc dnatsthgin eht no eldnac eht dethgil dah dna
”,velteD ,su fo owt eht tsuJ“  ksud ot
rebmemer su tel oS .wohemos ,eb tsum yeht nekorb teY
”.od ylniatrec I ...I“
,erif eht ta gnirats llitS
”.evaheb ot woh wonk ot deen ssalc fo sevlow eW
,eugnot ym naht erom nesool ot stnaw dratsab ehT
.resolc denael eh sa kcen nat eht fo kcab eht delkcit shtaerb mraw s’tnuoc ehT ”.joviliM dneirf
.tengam a ot nori ekil meht ot nward
,derepsihw velteD ”...rewueiD tnuoC“
.sretrauq suoromalgnu eht otni velteD dewollof renreW
.dennirg tnuoc ehT
?su no stup yteicos slocotorp citoidi esoht lla fo og tel ew t’nac yhW“
.sdrow txen sih llats ot tsuj ydnarb fo plug gnol a koot tnatnuocca ehT
,pu tohs eh sa elbat eht no nwod ssalg sih demmals ohw ,velteD nihtiw drohc a kcurts sdrow esohT
,sredluohs esoht no gnol oot dnoces a tsuj
.emahs ni ylthgils nwod gnileviws morf srae sih pots t’ndluoc tub
taht ekam lliw mrots eht diarfa m’I ,tnuoC yM“
.seye sih otni dewolf regna toh sa ylwols deddon nafetS  ”.rewueiD tnuoC
.rood nepo eht ta ylknalb daeha dezag yeht sa rehto hcae revo depard llits smra
”.joviliM retsiM ,taht tuoba wonk t’nod ...I“
yleerf pird sraet sih tel eh
:yltfos gniyas erofeb ,redluohs s’velteD ffo pils mra sih tel yllanif nafetS
.nirg sih raeh dluoc velteD dna
,mra lufrewop a yb pu dellup gnieb flesmih tlef
.detaeh emaceb eciov siH ”.evol ton
.sbreh dna rettub enif ni detaoc
.eldnac edisdeb eht tuo welb dna sehtolc nwo sih devomer nafetS nehw
thgils A ”.tnuoC ,tseretni ym fo ton erew noitasrevnoc eht fo scipot eht diarfa m’I“
”,seitilamrof ruoy htiw ffo doS“
.kcab sih dniheb smra lufrewop sih gnissorc
esoht fo ytilibisnopser eht si ,yletamitlu
.enola saw nafetS
,repsihw a ni desaet nafetS ”,on yas nehT“
:nuf rieht dah skooc eht elihw niks eht evas ot deganam stnavres ehT
kcab s’velteD nwod rehtruf levart ot wap thgir sih gniwolla
”.htnom txen enilednA gnicrovid eb ll’I“
”.ti wonk uoy dna ,em htiw did uoy gnihtyreve od ot detnaw uoY
.emalf yrgnuh a ;gnignol A
,oga emit gnol a seviw rieht rof tlef ylno dah yeht rehto hcae ni gnihtemos dezingocer sevlow owt eht
,edirP yppaH  .stsacdop ruoy
;tnemom eht ta seussi ssalc yna tuoba ssel erac t’ndluoc eH
.srennaM .lortnoc-fleS“
nafetS yb detpurretni saw tub
,dedaeh-toh eht syawla :nafetS
.dneirf sih htiw pu tpek ylerab velteD
.raef gnilbmeser gnihtemos htiw tnatnuocca eht ta dekool renreW
.renreW moor s’tseug eht ni peels nac uoY“
,enohpelet eht revo dias dah eh
snoom lluf niwt ekil seye wolley owT .ria lausnes
.nafetS ton ,rewueiD tnuoC
.yletanoitceffa nwo s’dneirf sih gnilzzun noos daeh krad sih
.nwod gnillaf fo ksir on saw ereht wenk eh
”?eugnot ruoy nesool lliw ydnarb enif emos spahreP .elbadnatsrednU“
”.knurd er’uoy nehw ressip a er’uoy dna etal gnitteg s’tI“
”,moor s’tseug eht ta thgin eht gnidneps eb dluow joviliM retsiM thguoht I“ ”!yawa
.srolehcab llits er’ew ekil
.yliria tnuoC eht dias
,ekas 'semit dlo roF“
,nibac etavirp sih ni ,ereh dnekeew a gnidneps detseggus rettal ehT .enilednA htiw
”eriF dna ydnarB“ saw sihT
,seirots enecsbo gnirahs
”.sriatspu ylbatrofmoc erom knird dna klat nac ew tuB“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sriats nedoow eht no spetstoof yb dewollof
nwad morf gnihsif eci
,doow hserf htiw ti ekots ot emoc dluow enoemos fi ylfeirb derednow eh dna nwod dniw ot gninnigeb saw mih fo tnorf ni erif ehT
.erised gnimlehwrevo sih tsiser dna yned ot deirt eh sa desolc seye sih
.nwad retfa yletaidemmi yawa tnes eb lliw eh ,sselehtenoN“
,swap s’nafetS ni taoc sih rof tuo dehcaer rettal ehT
,dias eh neht ,dewollof ecnelis trohs A
,snoinapmoc sa dniw gnilwoh eht dna
,ylkeem detsetorp velteD
roirefni sa flesmih was flow nat eht taht
”.su htiw thgin eht dneps ot joviliM retsiM rof yrassecen si tI“
.enola em stnaw eH
,uoy dnif ot ereh emac I“
.sdnoces lareves rof rehto hcae ta deralg owt eht sa stsif otni dellab swapdnah ,evisnefed dnats sih
.tnuoc eht morf trons evissimsid A
.retsam sih ta dekool renreW
,reirret dna tnuoc eht neewteb dehcram velteD ”.tsisni I“
.thguoht fo enil taht dellik velteD .oN
.dlrow eht tegroF
tnagele sih gnitautnecca
,flow eht thguoht ,eduR
,krow drah hguorht dimaryp laicos eht gnibmilc
.oga htnom a naht ssel elttil
.tcudnoc reporp ni eveileb I“
-rewueiD tnuoC- nafetS
”.emas eht od ll'I .ajidiL tegroF
,otsug htiw kroc eht tuo dellup dna ydnarb fo elttob eht koot nafetS
,yltalf velteD deilper
.ti did eh ,gnihtemos od ot detnaw eh fI
,nafetS emalb ot deirt velteD
”.elihw a rof ereh yats rehtar ...d’I“
,thgif ot detnaw eH
,serusaelp tsap fo mih dednimer dnim sih fo edis enO
,tsehc s’nafetS morf yawa flesmih dehsup eH
.ydnarb eht no hcamots sih ni gnirettulf mraw eht emalb ot deirt eh sa flow rehto eht morf htgnerts dna taeh eht tlef velteD
.riahc tevlev eht no niaga nwod deppolp