.meht erofeb retnab gnilrufnu eht ni derutparne
.noitpecxe eht erew yeht hguoht
”.ecitcarp doog eb dluoC“
.enips sih pu elgnit a tnes tI
”…ssarg dna trid tfos eht ni dnuora gnillor
.sregnarts ekil t'nseod dna yhs tsuj s’eH“
knurd ton dah ohw sretnuh ot
rof s’taht ecalp A
emirp a rof aiglatson lausu eht htiw nialpxe ot no tnew eh sa
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.meht dnuora gniworg erew taht snoitcere fo noitcelloc demahsanu yrev eht ot derutseg dna denraw arakaS
,xnyl eht esaet ot no mih gnivird ssenhsarb fo wolg mraw eht deyojne
.wonk uoy ,ecneirepxe tog ev’I tub
.deb ni saw ronoC
seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”.detcartsid teg t’nod ohw seno eht gnieb tuoba gnihtemos ,oN“ .arakaS dias ”,sakajraH saw taht ,oN“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
em no selkcus eH .uoy llet em tel
tfahs gnineffits sih dna arakaS htoB
”,won taht gniyas er’uoy oS“
”?ytinutroppo eht rof drawrof flesruoy gnittuP“
,rehto hcae tnaw dluoc noitisopsid rieht fo nem owt ylno yaw taht ni mih detnaw eH
”lufrednow sdnuoS“ .detaerc
teB“ .noitanalpxe rehtruf yna htiw tem ton
,ecaps dedeen netfo aneyh ehT
”.sruoy fo taert citoxe taht tuoba yas ot doog gnihtyna evah uoy t’nod ,arakaS ,yaS“
.tips gnikooc desu-gnol a ekil
erom erehwemos og ot deen I dna uoy kniht I“
,retnuh fo dnik deggur A“
,gnitlusni saw tI
.tsehc tfos s’regdab eht tsniaga daeh sih desserp dna ,deooc netram eht
,snaginanehs neknurd naht nosaer rehto on rof yrcraw a tuo detleb ohw xnyl ykcots eht ot
.erif s’egdol taews eht erofeb doots dna esor ylwols neht
suoicerp er’yeht ,hO ?he ,ynam oot ton tuB
.esirprus ni nepo gnuh wam s’xof eht deciton gnivah ylraelc ,tsehc sih elttar ot demees taht elkcuhc a htiw dias retto ehT
,sbro yzzuf s’xnyl eht dniheb yrotirret eht fo
”.flesruoy gnihtyreve
.flesmih ti gniwohs tuohtiw sevael eh retfa si tfahs s’nam ym gib woh tuoba klat ot deen t’nod I
edisa tes saw revoc ehT
,desum äemheP ”.hguoht doog os
.detaruc ylluferac os dah retto eht hcihw doom eht derettahs dna denaomeb arakaS
,droc elbakaerbnu na yb tsiaw sih ot deit
”,syad rof pop ot gniog saw ti ekil tleF
.regdab eht fo eciov eht demoob
”!flesmih rof ees dna deb ot em ekat ot emoclew s’eh ,llew
selcsum gninethgirf
.dehsinif regdab ehT
,enoyna tuoba tsuj ot nepo gnieb etipsed ,hguohT
shtaehs ruoy fo tuo gnikop spit der yciuj esoht morf llet nac I
”sthgiR gniggarB“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
.ikkuT htiw esolc eb tsael ta ot detnaw mih ni gnihtemos tey dna ,yas t’ndluoc yllaer arakaS
.ydob devrats-flah a htaeneb tsuj neddih
”!ylleb s’ydobyna ni splehw yna gnittup eb ot gniog t’nera ohw seno eht er’ew“ ,mih
,yks nepo na rednu thgin etanoissap a rO
?thgin dloc a rof ni s’eh won dna
.suoiruc era yehT“
,dne no dnats ruf nwo sih edam tI
,neht dna won ,llits ew tuB
.senob dna niks tsuj ton tub
.aneyh eht drawot delffuhs dna deggurhs arakaS
.htolcniol gnifahc sih no deggut dna ,worb sih morf taews eht depiw eh sa denialpxe eh
,sliart ynam sklaw ohw roirraw a si ronoC
,knird rehtona koot ,nwod meht tuohs ot desuap ,snaorg yb detpurretni saw eh erofeb ,ylevarg dias ikkuT ”,rebmemer ot gnuoy oot era uoy llA“
,mih ni anaS fo gnihtemos was eh spahreP
,em tuoba yas I tahw eveileb t’nseod ohw nam yna dnA
,sih saw ohw ,xnyl eht htiw ysatnaf siht ni tsol tsomla
”!wohs a deen llits ew dnA“
ot dedeen eh fi ,ylprahs tsisni dluow eh ,dlo ton—
,taht ekil nam fo knuhc lufituaeb
.egreme ot denimreted osla der dna thgirb esle gnihtemos fo pit eht ekil hcum
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”,ti tup ot yaw eno s’tahT“
.ediskcab sih no ylidaetsnu deyaws eh sa gnipoord erew sdileye sih tub ,hcum yfiralc t’ndid hcihw ,xnyl eht deppaY ”!lla ta toN“ .tfel dna pu sretnuh elbaulav esoht nehw enimaf a ro
.tohsrae ni erew namahS eht anaS fi ton yllaicepse
.hgiht renni s’ronoC dekorts eh elihw krims a htiw kcab knas neht
?taef a syad eerht rof spil ruoy neewteb kcoc a gnidloh tsuj llac uoy ,sakajraH
,htaehs sih kcilf ot nwod dehcaer dna demialc eh
.stoob niks revaeb sih pu derehtag dna denrut eh
.ti ssim dna knilb dluoc uoy gniteelf os enO
,hcuot sih ta dna
detamina os kool ton dluow yeht spahrep hguohT
.sdneirf ysae ,won ,woN“
”,yaw a dnuof uoy fI“
,eseht ot desu hguone llew erew ihovatneL eht tuB
?thgir ,sevlesruo ot lla thgin a evah ot evah
,retlehs rieht dnuof yeht hguone nooS
.yas ot gniog neeb dah eh tahw derebmemer neht dna
”,noitartsnomed a rof yrgnuh er’uoy taht
,wolga seye sih ,retto eht gnihctaw pleh t’ndluoc eh tuB
,ecneconni dengief htiw ,xnyL eht dias ”,em ot sdnuos tI“
.tiab eht ot esir ot deipucco oot saw ,sala ,aemheP
”!xof ,eert hcrib ynwarcs a ekil kool uoY
?eye ruoy ni emac eh taht“ ,äemheP derrup ”,emit eht gnittegrof ydaerlA“
”,eno doog a s’taht ,mhmM“ .wap sih ni daeh s’netram eht gnildarc yletanoitceffa dna nwod gnihcaer
,rettal eht tsgnoma saw arakaS
.pal s’elam rehto eht pota xaler ot ytinutroppo eht koot dna sgniggel dna htolchceerb s’netram eht pota tlik sih ssot ot netram eht ssorca drawkcab denael xnyl ehT
”,em pots ydaerla detam gnieb nam a tel reven I ,hO“
,arakaS saw taht xof ynwarcs dna teiuq eht morf
taht er’uoy fi ffo rehto hcae ekortS“
,yalpsid erar yrev a nI
”.thginot taem remrif
.mih tsniaga gnihsurb
.rethgual fo egrev eht no elzzum sih ssorca dehcterts krims a
,srallod eerht evah dluow
tca ot teg tol uoy ,won yhw si hcihW“
.desucxe eb tsum yllaer I tuB“
.erus ytterp m’I dias ikkuT ekil snoitcartsid tuohtiw evil em stel ti sI“
,noitartsurf fo tuo deffuh ronoC
.ycamitni ot emac ti nehw evisule saw namahs eht
od ot gniog yllaer erew yeht ,stirips eht yB
,reve ton ,yaw taht ni
,evisserpmi s’ti sseug ll’I
”.gnitnuhrevo tuoba luferac eb ot uoy llet I nehw netsil dluow uoy fo emos fi pleh osla d’tI“
prahs saw tnecs siH
”,oot doog sknits eh
.retlehs eht ssorca pael ot gniraeppa reed eht
,aneyh ym sa kciht sa tsomla ot esolc er’uoy dnA
.pot eht ta eloh eht tuo dewollib ti erofeb skcor detaeh-erif eht ffo gnimoc maets eht ni gnixaler dna
tsniaga ihovatneL eht nrut eh dluohs mih detiawa etaf ylgu nA
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.sniol sih ni gnihtemos derrits ikkuT …tey dna
.seirellag yrruFoS evitcepser rieht no
ekops eh yaw eht saw ti spahreP
,mih ot txen xof eht deksa dna drawrof denael eh
,arakaS ,snoitcartsid fo dnik tahW“
”.taht tcepser tsum ew dna ,nosaer a rof
.noitautcnup ni fi sa daerps ylizal sgel ,nwod kcab tas eH
emos fo ecaf eht ni yrevarb suotiutarg fo elat a erew ti fi sa
.snoillats yrenro ekil
,tsev dna htolcniol sih ni ylnrobbuts llits ,aneyh ehT
.yawa xof eht dehsup dna
.feihc sih saw taht flow a fo pmul taht dna
.ylsuoiruc edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc dna dedda ronoC
,netram eht dennirg ”,wonk uoY“
,ydaets dnah ym peek ot sucof emos kooT
.dereviuq sreksihw s’ikkuT
emit txen ni enuT
,mih gnizeeuqs ,ni gnisolc ylwols erew sllaw eht ekil
,snoitavreser sih dah llits eH
.sisahpme rof wap dezisrevo na htiw eye detcilffa ylremrof eht gnippuc
”sthgiR gniggarB“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     ”.gnihtemos ees ot etarepsed
.tseteiuq eht raf yb
.tsehc s’xof eht no ruf hsul eht hguorht meht nar eh ,yltneG
,meht fo tsom dah ev’I
,ebirt gnorts a ,ebirt doog A“
.degilbo yltnelis xof ehT
”.klof gnuoy su deef ro ,sevlesmeht deeF .esoohc ot dah sredle eht
.yks thgin gnilkraps eht ni wol
.ssenkrad eht hguorht yerp ees dluoc eh ekil
eht dna xof eht htob fo noitnetta eht werd dnuos stI
”!detam ton er’ew“
.naht erom gnihtyna raew ot deraeppa reven eh hcihw
,ti ssim did tsomla arakaS
.noinapmoc a naht ytisoiruc a fo erom mih edam ruf ydnas dettops-kcalb sih ekil
,yltbus delworg eH ”…arakaS“
,guj sih otni nwod decnalg arakaS ”,lleW“ ”?eb ot tuo ti edam uoy sa gib sa ti si“
”!snoitcartsid tuohtiw
:ezis naht erom srettam tahw tog s’eno sihT“
.esle gnihtyna naht esirprus fo tuo erom hguoht
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf ygolohtna na
,rood eht tseraen ,aneyH eht evas ,knard dna elpmaxe sih dewollof srehto ehT
.ycavirp no tnetsisni os s’ikkuT yhw tuo dnif ot
”,sgnivrac fo dnik eht ees dluohs uoY“
,delevirhs tiurf eht lla dna
,hcir dna cillatem
.sregnif ynob sih tuo dehcaer eh sa deooc ikkuT ”,etavirp
,netsil ot reraen werd xof eht sa derepsihw ronoC
.ruf dna ssarg yrd eht no
”…em rof ecalp eht t’nsi siht ,arakaS“
d’woh …wollef ym fo riap A
,ylnrobbuts kcab dekrab netram ehT
,nialpxe etiuq t’ndluoc eh yaw a ni tub
.yaw fo dnik retlehs uvvaL emas eht gnirahs a ni
.ni demihc netram eht
,aneyh devoleb sih erew deddeb reve dah arakaS sklof ylno eht
”,uoy fo rehtie sgniht eht eveileb ot drah ti sekaM .ot detam s’eh
”?arakaS ,rettam eht s’tahW“ ?yeht t’nerew ,siht
”.uoy esucxe lliw yeht dna
.yldettimda ,noitseuq riaf a saw tI
”,tol a detsaob ev’uoY“
”!ti htrow ereht uoy gnittup ekam ot deb ni hguone doog er’uoy erus eb tseb uoy ,telouH dnA .hguone noos erohc a tub
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.mirg saw ecaf s’ronoC no kool ehT
,spil s’aneyh eht ot eson dloc sih desserp dna revo denael xof eht sa hcnilf sa hcum os t’ndid tI
sloot enots rieht nwod tes dah yeht
.em tub ydobyna rof kaeps ot evah t’nod I
.gut a mih evag dna wap s’xof eht deppirg ronoC
wonk dluohs sretnuh eht lla fo uoY
”.sedart wef a naht erom delaes
eltsep dna ratrom a htiw thgin a ylknarf dna
aneyh fo dnik eht derutcip eh sa thguoht ni tsol
.rehtohcae fo llems eht dnats dluoc sretnuh neknurd ynam os woh gnirednow rof nevigrof eb thgim enO
ekil setsat kcoc doog a tahw wonk I esuac tsuJ
,retal tnemom a tuB
,pu sekaw kcoc eht nehW“
,drow yreve no dekooh erew srehto
.sgel ym neewteb rebmem ruoy gnileef dna
raf os dah setam gnieb sa tnuoc taht t’ndid deksa
,noitcejretni s’retto eht revo yaw sti deltserw eciov s’xnyl eht
,yltfos sakajraH dedda
,noitalever siht ta moor eht dnuora pu tnew elkcuhc A
.siht sa hcus roivaheB .su sa hcus nem
,nik gnieb sediseB
.draugraer nruticat eno sulp
.esneffo fo tnuoma llams on htiw dedda eh
.gnirepsihw dna spil yrd sih gnikcams
.taht detcepser eh dna
.snoisserpxe suoiruc htiw ecno ta sdaeh rieht denrut ohw ,retto
”!emirp ym ni llits m’I nehw neve dlo m’I ekil
,nem ot emac ti nehW
”?sakajraH ’,eert kao na fo htrig eht htiw raeb yldduc ,gib‘ ekil naem uoY“
na tsac eh ”,ew od
.kcab eht no tap gnigaruocne na netram eht evag neve xnyl eht dna
.drah taht edam syawla dah snomed eht tuB
.mra sih rednu netram eht dezeeuqs yltfos dna denialpxe eh
,nalp dnuos a ekil demees yldrah sihT
”.ti gnittup fo yaw nwo yM …evah I“
.hcum sa tsuj mih detnaw ikkuT taht llems dluoc eh dna
,slautir llac dluoc uoy tahw t’nerew eseht rof
,sgel dna smra sih
,tsehc mils ’sakajraH dnuora mra na dils äemheP ”,eno siht ,woN“
.noitisopsid ekil-esproc lausu sti naht os erom nevE
.suoivne sebirt rehto eht edam taht sesroh ruo tsuj reve t’nsaw ti ,wonk uoY
,srae yffurcs dna daorb esoht tsniaga spil sih desserp arakaS .esolc ni denael eh sa etam sih erussaer ot gnipoh
,lla retfa ,garb sretnuH
,smurd fo dnuos eht revo
?uoy edisni mih teg t’nac uoy tub
,ydobyna gniht tsal eht saw stirips eht fo htarw eht dnA
,skcor gnimaets eht ediseb morf delbmur telouH ”,wonk t’nod I“
.drawrof gnivom morf mih peek dluow taht
,gnorts oot ton ,ydob ywenis eht saw ti spahreP
,sretnuh wollef rieht nihtiw retsef etah tel ot ton wenk feihc doog A
.ytilibarenluv fo wohs a saw tI
,ronoC ta ezag suoiruc a tohs dna denrut eh nehW
flesmih tegrof t’ntsum ,xof
gnuoY saW dlroW eht nehW ni yltnecer tsom
,sgnirehtag thgin lla erew esehT
!eye ym ni emac uoY“
,detum saw tnecs siH ”?evah ton“
”.retal erom rof maercs em ekam retteb uoy ,esac taht nI“
.wap s’ikkuT fo dloh koot yltneg dna wap eno detfil ylwols eh
.tesnus ta dedne serohc ihovatneL eht roF
,noitatiseh s’tnemom a sa hcum os tuohtiw ,oS
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
.sevlesmeht stirips eht yb deralced egnellahc elbatnuomrusni
,tsehc eht ni efink a ksir yeht tsel
,yletilop dewob ronoC
,derutpac yeht segatsoh eht rof erew seitivitca hcuS
dah eh ysatnaf siht ni tsol emaceb eh sa ffo gniliart ,desum xnyl ehT
,flesym nees ev’I tahw tsurt ot referp I
ruf esraoc ,trohs sih fo noitasnes ylkcirp eht gniyojne ,s’ronoC ot redluohs sih desserp eH
”?ikkuT ,ti tup uoy
”.kcoc sih dnuora elzzum yrgnuh a gnivah fo syad owt retfa enob a no gnittup strats nam a taht“
,snoinapmoc ydwor fo dnabraw gnorts-ruof a yb deknalf
yltnegilid sa erusiel rieht ot gnittimmoc
,ekatrap ot ecnatculer s’aneyh eht erahs lla ta ton did yltnedive yrev ohw ,xoF eht ”…snaem eH“
,erif eht otni taps eh
,sedis derracs dna ruf gniyarg ni retto delzzirg eht ot
,elzzum s’ronoC tfel lrans ehT ”.desucxe era uoY“
hcuot lanosreP
.nwod dniw ot nugeb ylwols dah pmac edisekal eht fo eltsub dna eltsuh ehT
detaroballoc ev’yeht emit hcae rof rallod a dah yeht fi ohw
.mraw uoy peek nac I ,lleW
”,mih ni ti stup ohw eno eht m’I ,sediseb dnA
nehW ”.yas ot gniog s’enoyna tahw erac ot srae ro
triks yggahs eht pota kcab tas eh sa rethgual elballortnocnu fo knirb eht no demees eh ,tcaf nI
”,neve dna stoor dna tiurf ylno no gnivil erew ew ,enog lla saw emaG .evrats did ew
,dehsinif eh nehW
,yldetaeper deneppah s’ti gnitseretni s’ti tub tol a t’nsi hcihw
selam fo gnirehtag eht ni gnikat ylidaetsnu fi yllareneg ,egdol taews eht dnuora wap a devaw eH ”!su …ekil“
.anaS htiw yrt ot detnaw syawla dah xof eht dna
.kcab ylidaetsnu dewob dna esor retto eht
srednaw ronoC ,dnatsrednu tuB“
ihovatneL redlo wef eht nopu dekool reven dah eH
.taerg oot saw noitommoc eht tuB
.tnemegnarra siht ni neve regdab eht revo derewot yldrah eh ,lleW
”?su etarelot ylerem yeht oD“
.noitnetta neddus eht morf deliocer tsomla aneyh eht
,regdab dna ,xnyl
.elzzum delzzirg sih otni dehcte nworf lanrete na
.sremmus os ro evif nihtiw
”.tuoba gniklat eb dluoc eh ohw rednow I“
,tlef ti woh nialpxe ot wam sih denepo aneyh ehT .dekrep srae
!taht wonk yeht dna
.aneyh eht egdelwonkca ot denrut eh sa
”?smialc ruoy ot pu evil yllaer uoy nac tuB“
emos dnuora spil ruoy parw ot erac uoy spahreP
”!taht dias reven I“
gnol sih eporg mrif
”,erar si tsaob uoy ytiliriv eniuqe taht tub
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.arakaS raed sih ot emac eh ,tsal ta
”!sredle eht tcepser“
.ti fo enon gnivah saw ikkuT tub
,tih remmus thguord eht nehW .sevael“
.ni tuc ylkciuq dna taorht sih deraelc xof eht ,oS
,lufrednow tlef tI
emirp-sih-ni-llits-dlo-
,meht nopu debuad snoitciped gnitnuh edurc eht denedlobme tI
,hgiht s’aneyh eht dezeeuqs ylmrif xof eht ,esnopser nI
?retfa mih ot detam tuo gnimoc tuohtiw htuom ruoy ni kcoc s’nam a htiw syad eerht dneps ot“
.enob gel taog niatnuom a otni snrettap evrac tub od ot gniht a ton dah I dna syad eerht rof edisni deppart erew ew“
”!ytilatipsoh gnicitcarp tsuJ“
.derac ronoC wenk eh tub ,truh tI
,staes sa devres taht spirts radec gnillems prahs dna ssarg teews fo seldnub eht no kcab denael ikkuT ”,owt
gnihtemos tlef eh nehw mih ekovorp ot raeppa ti did ron
,eenk eno no nihc
.gnisir saw esle gnihtemos erehw shgiht tfos s’xnyl eht neewteb nwod dnah eno dah ohw
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”,msaisuhtne ruoy rof ,lla ,uoy knahT“ .detnaw
.yalpsid lluf no stnemwodne s’retto
.sdal nuf lla er’ew taht dnif ll’uoy erus m’I“
,enod eb ot sdeen tahw fo erac ekat ohw su ot s’ereh“
,äemheP dna arakaS neewteb detrad seye s’regdab eht
,ikkuT rof hguone saw ti tuB
.deddeb eh ohw roirraw ecreif eht dna
:ereht ylbakatsimnu tub
.ecaf s’xnyl eht ni mlap sih devohs dna delworg retto ehT ”!kcA“
”.thgin doog a ereh netram elttil ylkcirp ym desimorp t’ndah I fi won thgir ti od tsomla d’I
.esruoc fo ,splehw eht fo erac sekat
,delevart dah aneyh eht secnatsid tsav eht nialpxe ot tseb rieht deirt taht serutseg gnipeews edam eh ,did eh sA
.aneyh gnitaerter eht dniheb desolc palf egdol taews eht ot ecnartne eht dehctaw ynapmoc derehtag ehT .enog saw eh
,tnecs sih ekil tfos dna yhtrae
ton eht fo thgis eht morf etsah ni detaerter kaeps ot tuoba neeb dah ronoC tnemeerga gnidnatsrednu fo rumrum ehT
,redluob a ekil saw ydob ywenis sih dedderhs taht sracs sseltnuoc eht fo hcaE
,nid eht revo detuohs-flah ikkuT ”,si tniop ehT“
,snikstug htiw meht denetsaf dna stoob eht no tup eh sa kciuq sa tsuJ
.tuocs retto dlo eht ot egamad ssel od dluow
”,dniw eht ekil dliw
.skcirt ynam fo elbapac eugnot deniart-llew a htiw ,ytrid
,stirips eht egarne yldetbuodnu dluow tca na hcuS
,gnihtyna gniraew eb llits ot ronoC morf trapa tsal ehT
!thgis eht etiuq eb ll’tahT
,arakaS no dexif saw ezag yleets s’ronoC
,sdneirf esolc yrev dna setirovaf s’rehto hcae ylpmis erew netram dna xnyl eht ,rehtaR .etam ton ,llew
,modsiw fo htlaew hcir a dednammoc eciov sih dna
.skcuf yad eerht tuoba seirots pu ekam ot deen t’nod I
”,ynapmoc eht yojne tsuj I“
”.ecneirepxe erom htiw nam a morF“
”,evorp ot gnihtemos tog htob ev’uoy ekil skooL“
.yletanoissapsid kcab delbmurg arakaS ”,taht
ehT	 ”.esroh dliw detirips a ni gnikaerb sa nuf sa saw mih gnikaerb dnA“
…ot elitsoh ton era ihovatneL eht em dlot arakaS tuB“
,yrd ot stlep hserf eht fo tsal eht gnuh dna
.delggig dna depissog taht seciov regae otni dedaf sdels fo eparcs dna senotspank fo gnikcalc ehT
,mih edam ti sa suoiruf sa tuB
,derac eh esuaceb siht did ylno eH
,sih fo gnoht taht neve saw ti spahreP
,hpmH“  ”yaw thgir eht tsuj ni tops eht tiH“
,mialc eht fo lasiarppa feirb sih retfa decnivnocnu ,retto eht dekaorc
niaga guj eht morf ylideerg deplug dna kcab daeh sih deppit xnyl detnecs-kciht eht
yrots s’yadoT dna
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
hcum os dettur owt uoy mialc ot yrt annog uoY“ ”?drazzilb taht rebmemer uoy ,retniw tsaL
…ruoy referp eh dluohs yhw dnA“
.sretlehs uvvaL detniop ,egral rieht fo htmraw eht ot koot ,revewoh ,srehtO .maerb dna ekip fo hctac s’yad eht detsaor dna knard yeht sa gnihgual dna gnituohs
”?enim ot ytilatipsoh
”,eno siht fo yraw eb uoy taht esivda ylno dluow I
.esir selkcah s’ronoC edam noisserpxe ehT
esoht ni noisnet eht dna selkcah desiar eht deciton dah arakaS ,mih ediseB .mih
.knard yeht simuK hcum woh ron tog yeht ydwor woh rettam on
,tnereffid yas em raeh ton ll’uoy dna
.smra sih dessorc ,uoy knaht
.rethgirb wolg ot demees seye sih elihw denediw elims yrgnuh s’retto eht dna
.gnihtacs morf raf enot sih ,egartuo fo yalpsid detareggaxe na ni smra sih pu werht netram ehT
deniamer dna dniheb dewollof ohw aneyh eht ot
”?ylleb s’enoyna ni splehw gnittup ton tuoba gniht ehT“
,thgin taht em stnaw
.ronoC morf naorg rehtona deticile hcihw
tseug rieht pu reehc ot erised a ro ssennrobbuts fo tuo ti eB
,redneval fo slufdnah htiw detnecs yllaitinI
”,uoy htiw ereh thgir si meht fo eno dnA
?em no edir a gnikat ,uoY“
.arakaS truh dluow taht gnihtyna od ot tnaw t’ndid eh dna
kciht gib a tog uoY
uoy tsniaga kcab ym gnivah deicnaf adnik syawla ev’I“
thguan a otni nrut annog s’taht tub
,deffins arakaS ”,wonk lla eW“ ”.uoy knaht
dedlof neht eson sih pu denrut xof ehT
,plehw a llits saw I nehw kcaB“
,taht yfsitas em teL
yltneitapmi toof sih deppat dna edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc netram ehT
.gniyas saw eh ,tcaf ni ,tahw revocsid dna gof decudni-ssimuk eht hguorht hsup ot koot ti troffe eht ta deknilb regdab eht ”,gniyas tsuj m’I“ .kcab eht no regdab eht deppalc dna dekrab ikkuT ”!wonk eW“ .dennirg telouH
nam eht rettalf ot stnaw yllarutan nam a dna
,erofeb ylluferac sretnuh eht fo hcae gnieye ylsuovren llits ,devomnu deniamer ronoC tuB
.tuhs elzzum sih tpek dna
”?uoy ot od dluow nam detam a gnihtemos ekil dnuos tahT
”,gniht eht s’taht tuB“
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,egdol taews eht dnuora eye niatrecnu
.eugnot sih htiw krow ot seog dna sgel ym neewteb daeh sih syal eno siht ,lleW
arakaS tsniaga wap sih fo kcab eht desserp eh erofeb ,ecno gniddon
:dnim ot emac brevorp dlo na dne eht ni tub ,suoremun ylniatrec erew yeht dna
.kcab knarhs dna tnih eht koot arakaS ,saw eh sa knurD .evohs
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer
,edisni dezeeuqs dah sretnuh dekan-flah ,gnilialf fo murcs eht litnu detiaw dna kcab doots ylesiw arakaS .edisni delip yeht ehcnalava na fo ecarg eht lla htiW .hcum os etiuq
,ikkuT ot kcab daeh sih detsiwt dna deplug arakaS .seot delruc htiw delkceh äemheP
.tca ot deirt eh gnuoy woh rettam on
,spuorg ni derehtag yehT
ro aedi na tog lla ev’uoy ekil sdnuoS“
,mih otni yaw sti dnuof wohemos dah ti nihtiw ssimuk eht lla dnuof
gnuh noom lluf A  2 fo 1 traP
.etam sih fo tnuocca tsenoh na evig ot detsurt eb nac retnuh a fi“
,yltcaf-fo-rettam delbmum aneyh ehT ”…ees I“
,tnemeerga fo ngis a ni ,oS
,kcen s’netram eht fo kcab eht delzzun xnyl ehT
”.deef ot shtuom osla er’yeht tub
.ekal llits ylhtaed eht ssorca derettiks dna senip eht hguorht demaerts thgil yrevlis stI
sih ffo wohs ot ton ylniatrec dna hcterts ot fi sa smra sih daerps dna kcab sih dehcra
”?fo yraw eb ot s’tahW“
,noitatuper roop fo esoht neve
.dlrow eht ni erac a tuohtiw
,gnuoy llits saw thgin eht tuB
,retnuh hcae ot pu saw
,trats eht morf raelc neeb ytsenoh lla ni dah taht
.ssimuk rof etsat on desseforp ohw
aniraco na ekil maets eht gnitarutas sllems elam fo ynohpocac eht fo pot eht revo edor ksum yretto siH .ni demihc ikkuT
.deltsirb netram eht
:ekila hcum mees t’ndid yeht
,tnemom a rof xnyl eht tnuat eugnot der thgirb sih fo pit eht tel arakaS ”.gnol
noitarolpxe rehtruf ot noitativni eht koot wap s’netram eht dna
,teef s’regdab eht ta dehcnub
,thginot erom hcum teg ton dluow yehT
tnatsni na ni dehsinav nirg citnagig s’xof ehT ”!su
,stuobaereht ro setamega sih erew hcihw fo htoB
,erif eht ssorca morf ikkuT delbmum
.nik yrev ruoy saw etam esohw tseug emoclew a ton
,yllacificeps ,sretnuh eseht neewteb
.xof eht denialpxe
.srevol ruoy tuoba yas“
,regdab eht fo eciov yldnik tub ,peed eht delbmur
…ot gnimoc dna ,xnyl eht dna ,regdab eht fo eerf gnimriuqs
,worbeye na desiar netram eht
,skcor eht tsniaga kcab ,ekiL“
.llew sa thgim eh dediced os dna
,etam s’retnuh emoS !efil eht s’taht
.mih gnitacoffus saw maets eht ekiL
,deltsirb sakajraH ”,os erom dnA“
eerht elohw eht rof
retnuh gnuoy a sa ti draeh d’eh
”?neht ,naem taht s’tahW“
.taews dna ksum fo tnecs eht debrosba yldipar maets eht
,ti etarelot ton did sebirt emoS
,delbmurg regdab eht
.reffo eht fo ecnatpecca etiuq ton tub
,guj a desiar retto—
…uoy dna ,raeb a ekil tliub si eh tuB“
,sey ho dna ,aneyh ,retto
”.tsriht fo eid t’ndid ew os wons fo sluflwob tlem dna peels ot deppots ylno eW !syad
,erew ihovatneL lla sa
,elgnit enips sih edam sserac eltneg s’ikkuT
redlo eht ,ikkuT ”,sdaL“  .tuhs revoc eht dellup dna meht dniheb ni deppils yltaen neht
”,doog yna uoy fo rehtie od t’noW .plehw a gnilddoC“
.nettogrof yltnerappa saw ti
,edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc retto gniyarg ehT
”!uoy tuoba dias ev’I sgniht doog eht lla retfa dnA“
”,nwo sih no ilevuK gnivael ekil t’nod I
.mih fo edis rehtie no shgiht kciht eht no smra sih detser dna
.lrans ylgu na dehsalf ronoC hcihw ot
.mih fo tuo efil eht gnihsurc
retlehs a sdrawot deztlaw yeht sa htrof dna kcab gnihsols stnetnoc etihw ylkcis eht
.daeh sih detlit retto ehT
.tnemeerga fo don a htiw rehto hcae ot gnikool sretnuh eht fo hcae
,dehsinif telouH
”,naem I tahw teg uoy fi
.selbuort sih rof ecaf sih ni gnulf gnoht nikskcub dedracsid s’ikkuT tog dna
,tseretni fo wohs a ,ylthgils delrufnu sgel sih dna
,regdab ,xnyl ,netram—
,slautir ton ,llew
,ffuh detnioppasid a dna hgis a saw erehT
sah arakaS semit fo rebmun ehT
,ihovatneL a fo ssel yna em ekam t’nseod
,erif ytsaot a deips yeht nihtiw dna
.niaga ecno mih nopu dexif seye gninrub s’ikkuT ees dna daeh sih esiar ot ylno
,netram decaf-regae eht ta neht
,ylird delworg äemheP ”,hO“ ”.eye ruoy ni dneps sih teg seod meht fo eno fi nevE .thgin a rof ,driht a rof moor evah su fo owt ,lleW“
yas ot tnaem d’eh esle gnihtyna neeb dah ereht fi dna
,eciov gnimoob s’äemheP ni tuC ”?ya
,ni demihc arakaS ”,haeY“
”?mih fo pot no ,uoY“
,dias ikkuT ”,lleW“
)yltsom ro( dekan deppirts—
,skool tuoba erac ot seye on sah ti
”?äemheP ,neht em niart uoy t’nod yhw ,llew
eht leef dna tnecs sih llems oT
elims yoc a dehsalf spil siH
.htolcniol rehtael
eno siht piks esaelp
.yltneitapmi roolf eht pmuht ot nageb liat ddo sih elihw
.evitpeced eb nac skooL“
.guj eht htiw deipucco regnol on saw elzzum sih ecno
.retto eht detnaw eh wenk arakaS
,ohw floWcaM boR dna ,xoFarakaS yb
,srehtaf tnaw uoy naht sretnuh erom tnaw uoY“
?thginot detseretni t’nsi ehs
elam revetahw fo deb eht ni thgin a dneps ot elba gnieb“
.stirips fo lliw eht neve ro ,tcnitsni emos tsuj saw ti ebyaM
”,su ekil nem htiw smlauq on sah ebirt ehT“
,dehpmurah ikkuT ”,owt uoy dnA“
evitressa tub ,eltneg a xof eht gnivig
.regnuh dna ,animats
,ekal llits eht ediseb serif gnikots emos
.erif eht otni simuK ruos taps dna elzzum sih morf guj a derewol eh sa regdab eht derruls
”sthgiR gniggarB“   yojne esaelP
”.emoclew reporp a roirraw gnorts gib eht evig ot deen ew ekil“
.sselehtenon deirt dah yeht tub
yeht sraeps naht rehtar tuB
.rebmem ruoy gnirehtal eugnot
”!syad eerht rof kcoc sih dekcus evah ot gnimialc naht elat rellat neve na s’taht nehT
.nam rehtona htiw gniyal nam yna htiw melborp on sah ebirt eht“
.sseworp sih ot tlusni siht eunitnoc ot erised on htiw
.deggurhs ynapmoc ehT
.thgin siht morf thguos dah yeht tahw dna
?gnihtemos ro ti ekil yeht diD
”?wohemos mrotswons a desuac ti
,gninraw a sa tnaem neeb d’ti
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
”!ylleb ym ni ytnelp dah syawla I tub“ ,dias sakajraH ”,mih rof kaeps t’nac I“ ”?syad eerht eseht ,tae ot deen yna leef t’ndid“ ,lacitpeks
.nwad ta krow ot tes dah yeht sa
.larutanrepus tsomla saw dewollof taht tsul eht dna
.efirts fo sremmus owt-ytnewt sih ni tol a hguorht neeb dah ronoC ,lla retfA
,nialpmoc ot nageb xnyl ehT ”-tub ,yeH“
,dnim s’enoyna ssorc neve t’ndid noitcerid niatrec a ni sgniht ecrof ot thguoht ehT
,thguoht taht ta deredduhs dna desuap xof ehT
slleweraf wef a retfa dna ,yllautneve
ees ot referp uoy hcum woh“
,doowerif sih lla yawa evag rerehtag a fo loof emoS .taht fo erac ekat ot woh wonk I ,elbuort oN
nik rieht enola tel
.äemheP ot gniklat saw eh hguoht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,yldekciw dennirg sakajraH
.acissarb dliw ekil ,yreppep dna
”?seibab ynam sa evah t’nseod ebirt eht snaem su gnivah esuaceb enimaf a tuoba yrrow ot evah t’nod ew“
,ydob delcsum yldilos dna ykcots llits
”?ecalp laiceps a yhw oS
.knird gnol rehtona koot eH
”,drazzilb eht gniruD“ .detrons ikkuT
,kcits a htiw erif eht gniddorp retfa
.gurhs ot netram ynit ylevitarapmoc eht fo edis rehto eht dnuora morf mra sih detfil ohw
”.nrael ot owt ro gniht a evah llits lla t’nod sduts gnuoy uoy decnivnoc ton m’I tuB“
.stsen yzoc ni deldduh yeht erehw spoteert eht morf deohce llits snoegip fo sooc gnilbraw eht dna
.taht ekil yrgnuh kool uoY“
,guj yalc a deirrac hcae
,eugnot sih dekcilc telouH
arakaS ta dennirg netram ehT
,ti tog ev’uoy elihw enif s’rogiv gnuoY“
.thguoht emos retfa ,deilper xof eht
.yawyrtne eht revo gnignah yrovi denekcalb fo eceip a yb dekram
.arakaS“ .dekrims ikkuT
tur niatrec rof yas nac I ohw owt ylno tem ev’I sraey ym lla nI“ .tsap gnol
,ylleb s’regdab eht tsniaga kcab tser daeh sih tel
!gniod s’eh tahw tuo erugif ot emit dah s’ohw enoemos morf owt ro gniht a nrael lla dluoc uoY
.ti swonk dna ,part a otni deklaw s’eh nehw seod retnuh a yaw eht decamirg retto ehT
.deprihc sakajraH ”?sredle ruo morF“
pu ti delttob eh
.tlik sih netsafnu ot dedeecorp ylisub eh
,enola ezag sih htiw llaw eht tsniaga xof eht sserp ot detnaw eh fi sa arakaS ta derats telouH ”,oS“ .edistuo ssenkrad dloc eht otni dehsinav dah eh ,taht ekil dnA
”.ti tae ot nerdlihc gniraeb naht ni doof gnignirb sklof eroM“
,demmuh regdab ehT
deksa d’ydobon hguoht
.ezeerb thgin eht ni gnihgien sesroh eht dluow yeht naht dnim erom on sukcur eht diap ebirt eht dna
.ikkuT ta kcab neht dna
.taert a ton s’eh dna ,citoxe ton s’eh ,esaelP“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dellarhtne ssel hcum saw ronoC tuB
nworg nam a sa tub
leef dluow ti teb I“ ”.ti gnivig fo daetsni ti sekat eh lufetarg m’I semitemoS .gib yliracs s’tI“
,mialc evisserpmi dna dlob a si tI“
…ym yas ot raf os og dluow I
.gnol sa ton er’uoy fi neve
.wolg sllaw edih reednier yvaeh eht gnikam thgil gnirekcilf sti
.eson sih tsniaga ruf yarg ,dloc taht fo eltsirb
.noitaterpretni tnereffid a dah eh desoppus eh