.ecnalg sseldrow ,lautum a degnahcxe I dna diS ,oS
,heH“    .detrap ew tnemom eht ria rof depsag I litnu
.elihw a rof nwonk d’yeht em dlot ylmlac daD dna moM
,klawedis ot klawedis morf deggoj ew sa em dlot eH
.hctiwt liat yhsub ym dna
,diS morf detcepxe reven I yaw a ni dessik eW
.roolf yrotcaf deraelc eht fo dne rehtraf eht no gnivom nees eb dluoc setteragic til dna smaeb thgilhsalF
,slworg htiw dexim elggig A
.erofeb derolpxe reve su fo rehtien seirotirret eht leef dna
,em ta nwod detnap eh sa nirg siH
”.I od rehtien dna
eW“( yhpargonrop yag gniyub deppots I taht
.ecnartne ym ot pu ti denil aneyh eht dna stnemtsujda wef A
,gnihtemos tsniaga dehsurb yltneg ti nehw deppots tfahs kciht sih ,nehT
.nihc dna epan s’aneyh ym revo lla stej toh ni detpure muc sa kcab daeh ym gnignah neht
fI“( emit doog a detnaw I fi spots tser ro skrap eht ot gniog dediova I taht ,)”?hseepac
er’uoY“  .gnitnap sih dniheb romuh htiw ekops eH ”.omoh oN“
.maerd a t’nsaw ti
.dnah ot ydaer si ti
,hguoht dne eht nI .ylgnisirprus
.enips ym nwod nar llihc A
.tuoba dna tuo saw ytic eht ni poc dna rethgiferif yreve fi sa dednuos ti ,seitirohtua eht fo gnikaepS
,yrrehc ym deppop ohw aneyh eht ,nifareS diS diD
.ainraN dnif ot tesolc eht ni hguone peed sdneirf egelloc dah dna
ti pu deppal eugnot ym ,nehT
,rehtegot rewohs a gnirahs yb emit devas I dna diS  ”.yrros naht efas retteb
”.éhcuoT“  ”.thginot
”.eb nac I sa suoires sA“  ”?lexA ,suoires
.sey lufdeen a tuo rettu em ekam ot swap gnorts sih rof ylno
”—t’nod I fi em llik gnikaerf lliw sklof ym tuB-tuB“
,worg ot detrats kcoc sih kcus ot egru eht sa hcum sA
,sraet dna sdrow lufetah htiw decal hctam gnimaercs a fo daetsnI
,detapissid sllihc ehT
.’ecapsbus‘ llac dluow yad tneserp eht ni sruf yag tahw derevocsid I dna retal sdnoceS
,nisnocsiW fo sretniw citcrA eht gnivarb ton s’eh nehw noitcifnaf dab gnidaer emit sih sdneps ohw
,pal gnikahs ym no delbmert liat ym
.leets gnitsur dna retsalp llaw
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT    .dneirfyob
uoy…uoy nehw modnoc a desu uoy ti ekat I“
.foor gnitsur a htaenrednu ria looc eht ni gnizeerf
,nevaR ehT fo tuo enecs a ekil dekool senilyks eht revo sarua wolley ehT
.peels ot ffo detfird ew sa em denoops eh elihw
,levon plup yag detartsulli na debban dna .D.I ekaf a htiw erots tluda eht otni kcuns I noonretfa emas ehT
.orb ,uoy evol ’nikcuf I…I
.kcab mih dessik I sa naom ot em gnisuac
.esacriats eht yb lerrab a otni modnoc desu eht dessot aneyh yM .llaw eht otni deddebme tenibac enol eht ni slewot repap tfel reganam tsal s’tnalp eht lufknaht erew I dna diS
.esuoh eht fo tuo em dekcik sklof ym ecno od d’I tahw deraef llits I tub
.taorht gnitaews ym fo mottob eht epacse ot psag a gnisuac
.pu kcab desserd ew sa dlrow eht fo pot no tlef dna ,ssik esirprus a
.ria nmutua-dim eht ni derevihs tsehc erab yM
,)”.yag ro thgiarts ,siht uoy llet d’eW
.taefed thgils ni deggurhs I
.elzzum krad ym fo pit eht no flesti dnuof tekcor der taht dna
,goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
wenk I dna ,niaga dessik eW
.sthguoht ruo tuo gninword tsomla
?t’ndluow meht ekil stnerap gnirac tahW
mih ot gnidael eson dloc sih dna
aneyh knup eht gnitcepxe ton
,tihs ticilpxe taht fo yna gnidnif dna moor ruoy dnuora gniog ylliB ro araM deen t’nod
thgiseye reporp fo kcal rieht ot sknaht ,revewoH
,mutorcs ym morf gnisir mutnemom a derebmemer ylno I
.moC tod rettiwT morf ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb
s’tI“( modnoc a ro ebul rof ksa syawla dluoc I rebmemer ot
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
em fo tcepsorp eht ta pu netfos dluoc stnerap ym
ecnis ytilauxesomoh ym tuoba nwonk d’yehT
,diS dneirf tseb sih ot tuo emoc tsuj dah xelA ,emit tsaL
”…lexA ,larutan a er’uoy ,fmM“
a suorutnevda dna gnuoy eht evig ot si
eveileb yldrah dluoc ti neve ekil
yna dah reve I fi moM ot og ot dna
.daor eht gnola yaw ruo gnimoc sthgil eulb-dna-der was ew fi nib hsart ro hsub a dniheb gnidih
fo sreyal eht yb delffum ,yawa selim morf sneris gnihceercs dna stuohs tnatsiD
nwod srexob der sih dediug diS litnu
,levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.emit emas eht ta gnissapsert elihw evol ekam ot tuoba
.gnola emac I erofeb nam dlo sih morf dehctans ylekil
.ria eht detaemrep ezalba doow tneicna fo llems ehT .denrub ereiviR
.smaerd tew tevlev fo gnitsat dna
.etanoissap dna peed
,oot yag eb ot deneppah diS
.moc tod rettiwT morf
,edis eht ot dedracsid erew sksam anadnab ruO .gniroolf delit eht no tuo dial d’eh lewot eht no rehto hcae morf ssorca deggel-ssorc tas ew sa dednuofbmud ,denediw seye s’aneyh dettops ehT
,erutnevda ot ,tuo og ot nosaer
.elims gnippihsrow ym ni ti ees dluoc eH
eciton ll’eh kniht uoy oD“
.em ta nwod derats eH
,deksa yletamitlu I ”?diS“
.em rof s’emas eht kniht I…hguoht wonk’Y“
,kcab sih dehcra dna detnap eH ”…tihs gnikcuf
.spoc yna rof tuo kool ot detpo sdneirf rieht fo eno esac ni ,skcart ruo gnirevoc rehtruf seiks yduolc eht rof doG knahT
uoy era ,kcuf yloH“  2 fo 2 traP
.edisni em eta ti taht hguone gnol
!edud ,uoy ekil yob A
.lexA ,hcum oot s’ti fi pots ll’I dna ,lla ta niap yna leeF
”?tihs a evig t’nod sklof ruoY ?yllaeR“
.doolb ward ylraen hteet sih ekam ot hguone gnorts msagro na tuo delworg dna redluohs ym otno delrans diS ,retal sdnoceS
,gniksa htrow si tI
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.krad eht ni deldnof ew sa niaga gnissik dna gnihgual erew ew litnu ,I saw sa
esuoh eht ot slrig gnirb ro etad t’ndid I yhw tuoba snoitseuq eht dediova d’I
”?lexA ,uoy nac ,siht fo hguone teg t’nac
.edistuo dloc eht morf etalusni ot elttil did tnalp noitcudorp desolc A
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
,tluciffid tahwemos stroffe gnilkcus ym edam tI
N“ .tniat ym evoba gnignah sllab sih delkcit dna deggaw liat ym nehw yllaicepse
,dedeen yllaer si egaruoc nehw taht os
,os deerga eh nevE
,sneet knup owt ,erew ew erehT
.sterces fo sllehsbmob hcus retfa secaf s’rehto hcae ees ot dedeen eW .won rof
.naorg a otni desserppus elkcac aneyh a rof evas
,sicoV sumoD yb
.ecaf gnihsulf ym koohs I hcihw ot ,deksa eh
.evirra reve yad eht dluohs ,’elbuort yug‘
,ereiviR ni efil gnuoy ym tuohguorht raey eht fo syad eht lla fO
.aneyh eht ot detsisni I ”.ecneulfni dab a ton er’uoY“
”…ti s’taht haey ,mmmM“
,emas eht gniod sih ro nwo rieht no gnivom seenk ym ot eud rehtiE
mraw tsehc ym gnikam
.resolc em dleh eh dna
tsaL“( dlot I ohw revo luferac ylemertxe eb I taht
.kcab ym ffo ssa hctib gniggan reh teg ot reh dekcuf I“
.ssenredliw nagihciM eht ni tuo pmac ypareht noisrevnoc emos ot og ot deen a ron
.kcoc gnikael nwo ym rof yltsom
.thgiN s’liveD no
.digir werg smra s’diS  ”?uoy ssik…I naC“
.kcen ym fo kcab eht deppin diS  ”?omoh on…“
wap eno htiw gnitabrutsam em hctac ot moorhtab eht ni em no ni deklaw moM
.etunim dilos a rof tuo dekcalb I nehT
.sriatsnwod deohce esion gnihsarc a litnu…
.thgir a tsuj ton ,egelivirp a
.derednaw dna tuo dehcaer swap ruo
.gninraw tuohtiw emac dne eht ,retal setuniM
.ytisrevinu ta did reve
”…thgit-t os er’uoy ,xelA ,doG“
,sffuh dna sesruc luftsul fo gnirts a htiw detaeper eh
,sesuoh dna spoteert ssorca dellirhs skcurterif dna slortap ecilop fo smaercs eehsnab ehT
.yawa ti dehctans ylsseltroffe
.doohnam eht gnirevoc citcalyhporp ,kcils eht dnuora etadommocca ot ssa ym rof ylno
.gninnirg dna spil ym gnikcep neht ,ybraen
.nemodba ym no wap mraw A .sdniw gnilwoH
,)noisiv thgin no gniyler fo daetsni sthgilhsalf dias thguorb yeht gniredisnoc ,os demussa I(
,srexob ruo ni srevoc deb sih rednu deppils dna ffo deird ylkciuq ew sa
”.diS ,uoy evol I“ .delggig I
,rood tnorf eht ni tnew eW
yb dna raef revocsid ot
,dedda I sa mih deifsitas don elpmis A  ”?yakO
.eciffo s’reganam eht fo tuo yawriats nepo eht nwod dekaens eW
,sicoV sumoD yb
.em neve desirprus hcihw naom gnitarebrever ,peed a yb dewollof saw tI
!hha—em gnikcuF !hgn—
”?erofeb enoyna htiw gnihtyna enod reve’Y…Y“
,ti yb draug-ffo thguac saw aneyh egral ehT
.deb ot og ylkciuq ot dedeen ew
,skcab dehtolcnu ruo ,stsehc ruO
,em ot derepsihw diS
”.lexA ,ti ksir uoy ’nittel ton m’I ,dneirfyob gaf ruoy sA“
”.rehtien eM“  ”.tey toN…oN-
?seirots tsohg gnillet ew era yhW
,egarednu erew ohw sruf ot dednetxe ylno wefruc ediwytic eht dna neethgie ydaerla erew diS dna em ,detnarG
,cificeps erom eb oT
”.yaw eht yb owt ot retrauq a s’ti syas hctaw yM“
,liat ym pu gnitloj ylneddus niap gniralf eht morf sraet kcab thguof dna decniw I sa toN
,sdrow dnif ot deirt dna kcoc sih ffo derettups I  ”?kcuf
.esuoh ym ot nwo ym no ti ekam neht ot dereffo I
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,kcab dial I sa em gnihcaorppa
,kcen ym gnilkcit htaerb toh sih fo tnecs eht ni dehsiler I
”.gnihtyna tog t’nod uoy em esimorp ot uoy deen annog m’I tub“
.wohemos su neewteb denessel pag ehT  ”.omoh oN
”thgiN s’liveD no gnicnaD“   yojne esaelP
,sredluohs ym dnuora depparw selcsum derruf sih fo htmraw eht tegrof reven ll’I
.hguorht yawflah daer d’I levon plup eht ro
,swaj ym gnitlem htmraw sti dna wam nezorf ym edisni gnikans eugnot aneyh regral sih
niaga dna ,niaga dna ,niaga dna ,niaga eugnot sih erised em edam tI .erom tnaw em edam hcihw rovalf ygnat a ot ti deneteews avilas siH
.sesion gnihsarc erom neve dna rethgual enasni yb dewolloF
.noissap fo level detcepxenu
.neercsno denord smoctis thgin-etal fo snurer sa renilcer etirovaf sih gnidnuorrus selttob reeb ytpme
elims deifsitas ,lufituaeb sih ot pu decnalg I
.wohemos ,tcnitsni no ylthgils daerps sgel yM
”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“
.rehtaf sih llet ot ton derad tub
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.mih ta pu gnihsulb ,naom rehtona kcab thguof I ”.pu tuhS-hS…hgN“
,pu gnittis elihw delkcuhc eh ”,yakO“
.detrops eh sredluohs gnorts eht
,wenk rehtom gnitod sih detcepsus diS ,elihwnaeM
00:3 erofeb esuoh eht ot kcab teg did I gnimussA .tihS
)saw eh ro( erew ew
.eciov wol a ni aneyh ym deksa I ”?gninrom eht ni
,VT eht fo tnorf ni gnipeels nifareS .rM yb gnissap dna su dniheb ti gnikcol
.tsehc sih ot esolc em llup smra gnorts s’aneyh eht tlef I
.8102 ni
,ni stnecs s’rehto hcae dehtaerb ew
?sevlesruo eracs ot yrt ew od yhw
,htgnel sih no taps dna
.T a ot ti deipoc dna
”,esrow ro spoc yb thguac teg uoy fi tif reggib neve na evah ll’yehT“
,)”.gnihtemos ro tsicroxe na teg ot su gnillet ,segassem eciov gnivael stnerapdnarg ruoy si deen ew gniht
,raew rehto hcae nees d’ew cirbaf fo sreyal rednu selcsum tlef yehT
,ni evil uoy moor a ni pu kooh t’nac uoy
.etal siht tuo eb ot desoppus t’nerew ew
.enot suoires a ni tuo detniop eh
,em dessik ylneddus diS esuaceb eciov ym ni truh eht deciton ev’tsum eH
,reeb renemhöB fo psiw a woleb etteragic fo ecart niht A .etsat d’eh denoisivne syawla d’I yaw eht detsat eH
,mih devol I hcum woh diS llet ot drow rieht deifed I meht dlot dna
ytinigriv ym esol ot detcepxe reven I
annaW…hguorht yawflah tneitapmi tog knaks eht tub
,gninepo s’eivom eht ot ralimis dna
.og ot emit saw tI
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
”.tihs diputs gniod sa stnuoc thgiN s’liveD no tihs diputs gnioD“ .pu ekops eh
.yawa kool ot ton derad eH
N“ ,yas ot rebmem sih ffo dellup I ,yltnatculeR
,skramer edins emos degnahcxe
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,em dlot eH ”?ti tog ,siht dnuora gnikcuf oN“
,gnimocemoh s’raey tsal gnirud kcihc eno siht dekcuF“
,tihs ho…ha ,fmM !fhmH“
.tuohtiw reven tub
”?huh ,ecneulfni dab a m’I sseuG“
gnieb sorb tsuj er’eW“  ”!hgN !ti wonk uoy-
,tuoba gniog sreciffo ecilop fo snezod eht gnidiova elihw
daD naht sdneirf tseb yag htiw ecneirepxe erom hcum dah ehs llet dluoc I ,ylsuoivbO
”…hcum oot s’ti fo em llet os ,uoy evol I
.erifdliw ekil doohrobhgien eht dnuora daerps drow gnivah enola tel ,gnitaudarg erofeb sselemoh gnieb ksir t’ndluoc eH
.uoy truh t’now I“
”.esimorp I .diS ,esruoc fO“
…dlrow eritne eht fo pot no tlef ew ,haeY
,doohrobhgien ruo sa scilohtaC detoved fo hcum sa t’nerew eW
.osrot dekan-flah nwo sih ot em dellup dna sredluohs ym dnuora demaor swap s’diS nehw ,revewoh
.xelf drawpu gniworg hcae htiw hsut ym dleh rehto sih sa wap eerf sih htiw keehc ym gnisserac
,)”.lla ta pu kooh t’nod uoy neht
,dluoc su fo rehtie sa hcum sa muc eht tuo denaelc eW
.derumrum eh ”,peels ot og dna pu tuhS“
.em ta kool ot daeh sih esiar ot stsurht eht desuap eh ”…tsuj…sorb
mih gnileef dna kcoc aneyh sih gnidir
dna pu dekrow em tog tahw derednow ehS
.ecalp sih rof ti dekoob ew ,suhT
,ytilaer elbarusaelp fo enalp rehtona ot delevart d’I ekil tlef I
;redisnoc ot sgniht lareves em deksa ylno yeht
,trihs-t ym fo meh eht nwod decart yldrawkwa swap siH
”!ereht tuo si ti enasni woh was uoY .lexA ,yaw ’nikcuf oN“
.rehto eht ni koob eht gnidloh dna
,raef htiw ecitcarp oT .llew sa yrevarb revocsid ot eniltuo sti gnicart
,tsehc gnirevihs ym gnitrofmoc sregnif dilos sih
tekcop kcab ’stnap sih morf modnoc a tuo gnihsif elihw delbmum eH ”.eno esu did I“
uoy evol yehT .hguoht ti naem I“
.od ot tuoba erew ew tahw ta yltoh gnitnap
.yldetaeper ti gninekcils
.taeh gnisir eht ot eud stekcaj ruo devomer yllautneve eW
.hguoht yrrow ot evah t’ndid I ,tuo denruT
deb ym rednu enizagam ytrid a derevocsid moM dna
no…ssapsert ew sa yas uoY“
.remmus eht ni reilrae daeha emac lla tI
,mih dnuora liat ym gnilruc ylsseldnim dna gnihsulB
,mih ta pu dekool I nehw teY
,rehto hcae fo tnorf ni lewot eht no gnileenK
.dlrow elttil nwo ruo ni erew eW
”?yrt a tihs yag siht gnivig peek ot ekil uoy d’woh ,neht lleW“
,gninnips tnew moor ehT
.nees eb ot erehwon ecneidua thgiarts a rof ecaf evas ot gniyrt morf mih pots ton did tI .wenk I
,emit emas eht tA
.daeh ym gnittap elihw derumrum eH
,moordeb ym otni kcuns d’I enizagam onrop yag eht devlovni laro yag rof teg dluoc I ecneirepxe ylno ehT
.niaga etatsorp ym dehcuot pit aneyh suordnow taht nehw rehgih evatco na emaceb drow tsal tahT ”!doG ,hgn hO
,redluohs thgir ym gnikcil
.dnik ni sgnileef esoht nruter ot
.kcuf ot detnaw I ,seY
.slirtson ruo gnipolevne ylgnimees ksum suoiciled eht ni dehsiler I dna
,ecneulfni dab a uoy redisnoc t’nod yehT
,kcoc erab ym dnuora gnisserac sregnif ylnaM
”,luferac eb I deksa ylno yehT“
,mih desitsahc I ”!sufood ,nigriv a m’I“
,ssenkcalb eht ni em ees ot elba sih fo seye lanrutcon lufituaeb esoht otni
,tnalp drojF eht noitnem t’ndid
?raef ew sgniht eht ekove ot lavitsef a dloh ew od yhW
,ytefas fo secnatsmucric ni
.uoy evol stnerap yM“
,rehtegot detnap ew sa dehcuot ylraen seson ruO
.nirg gnirorrim a otni denrut egaugnal luof gnisu morf noisserpxe desirprus s’diS  ”.em kcuf woN-
ruf ydob detrahcnu hguorht nur sregnif ruo gnittel
?meht emalb uoy dluoC
,niaga ecno dekrims eH
…ekil gnihtemos diova ot gnihtyreve gniod
.noitadimitni thgils ni neffits ydob ym gnikam osla elihw
”.lexA ,detsiwt seitnap ruoy teg t’noD“
.raf oot su thguorb ssendlob ym taht deraef I
.ssalc myg fo edistuo ,tsael tA
.retal stnemom ekawa em koohs eH
.mih fo pot no flesym gniworht yllaretil yb noitseuq sih derewsna I ,ylsselhtaerB
.thgin taht em rof dne eht eb d’ti thguoht I
.gninrom txen eht sklof ym llac ot dedeen llits I ?swen daB
gnirud…thgin loohcs a
.wap eht yb mih dniheb em deggard eh sa knalb tnew dnim yM
laiciffo tsrif ym gnivah
.ytrap eht denioj esle ydobemoS
.tnalp eht fo tuo dna ssenkrad eht hguorht kaens su eciton ton did sladnav fo puorg eht
.htraE ot kcab em dellup eciov s’diS tub
.loohcs morf emoh denruter I tnemom eht em dnuorg ot gniog os erew yehT
”.diputs gnihtyna od t’nod I dna“
”.xelA ,oot uoy evol I“
,stsurht etarepsed sih htiw enut-ni tnurg ,kcen ym ssik
,loow peehs ekil dehs sehtolc ruO
,kcen ym ot kcil mraw A
,em detnahcne ezag yleets A
)thginot ti gnideen detcepsus eh ,tuo denrut(
.eson sih fo tnorf ni gnivaw kcom
”.lrig taht dewercs
”thgiN s’liveD no gnicnaD“
?dneirfyob sih sa em ot refer
ti…t’nia ti wonk’Y“
,VT no nem eht ta gnikool ylteercsid syawla em deciton daD
eporg ylnam a sa hguoR
.spih erab sih delddarts I sa dnuorg eht morf em gnitativel
.siht enod I dah reveN .t’nsaw I ,oN
’elytsefil lufnis‘ a dah I kniht ton did yehT
.dnuorg eht ffo dekcik tsud litnu hctiwt liat yhsub ym ekam dna ,raluguj ym no elbbin
.ecneibma edistuo yb neddih naom gnilbmur siH
.mih ot resolc em gnillup erew stengam ekil
,gnitnuah eht fo ,stsohg eht fo tniop elohw eht taht eugra dluoc enO
”.toggaf a ekil zzij annog er’uoy dna drah taht uoy gnikcuf neve t’niA“ .ylyoc dekst eh ”…edud ,yag ’nikcuf oS“
tnemevom erutlucretnuoc eht gnirud tiorteD ni pu werg owt eht ,lla retfA .em devol yehT
.ot tnaw I esuaceb uoy gnikcuf m’I ,on ,oN
.su ediseb ti dracsid dluoc eh os pu smra ym desiar ylsseldrow I dna
,etoyoC triD yb daeR    .noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif osla nac uoY
.wal eht htiw tcaretni ot detnaw su fo rehtien
na ni detcennoc selzzum ruO  ”!ti kcuf…xelA…lexA ho…uoy…“ ,enim no dexifsnart seye ,shtaerb yvaeh emos htiw sdrow eht gnimrof deirt eh ”…uoy
,elzzum ym no flesti dehcte krims A
”...lexA ,yag gnieb er’uoy won ,fffP“  ”.oot od I…dna
no modnoc eht decalp ylsseltroffe eh sa noisufnoc otni denrut ezag gniveilebsid yM
”thgiN s’liveD no gnicnaD“
.kcab delims dna yltrohs delkcac eh
.ssendlob ot yaw evag egaruoC  ”.omoh on…haeY“
,llitS…tnecs s’knups ruoy thguac eh fi elcarim ’nikcuf a eb d’ti ,pmud ytic eht ta sruoh ynam os skrow daD“
.)nemow fo t’nsaw ti(
eno siht piks esaelp
,thgir sdrac eht deyalp I sa gnol oS ?swen dooG
.dnuor dnoces a rof og ot egru eht gnitsiser elihw ruf s’rehto eht gnibburcs dna gnioopmahs
.ylregae gniggaw liat sih htiw hcamots ym gnilkcit
y dnA !ha ,yag si sihT“
sselnu…uoy sselnu yag t’nia