”.ecno ta ni ekat ot tol a s’ti wonk I ,emit ruoy ekaT“
.mih ot resolc mih llup dna
.hcuoc eht no taes a koot retto ehT
redluohs s’enyawD revo ti epard ot mra thgir sih derewol dna pu smra sih dehcterts nomed ehT
.gniyalp tpek eivom eht morf dnuos eht sa
,dnah sih ni deraeppa reeb fo elttob a dna ,sregnif sih deppans dna pu dnah sih detfil eH ”.sserdda na ta
”.tnuocca ym no pots t’nod ,hO“
nihc s’enyawD ekat yltneg ot devom dnah eerf s’nomed ehT ”.mhmmmM“  ”!lufesu woH“
,os ro setunim wef a retfA
”?he ,pu uoy elir ot yb gnimoc nomed a ekil gnihtoN“
t’nsI“ .reeb sih derewol dna worbeye na desiar aimuhtipE
.elzzum sih no gnimrof elims a ,yltfos derrup nomed ehT ”,yltcaxE“   ”!oN“
.ereh yas ot desoppus saw eh tahw wonk t’ndid enyawD
,ruoh rehtona rof kcab eb t’ndluow etammoor siH
,revewoh ,eciov siH
.gnicar traeh sih ,yldipar meht neewteb dekool eH
.seirots trohs lareves dna
”?em rof taht otno dloH“   ”?tahW“
!ot detnaw eh ,esruoc fO
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.enog saw aimuhtipE tuB
denediw seye s’enyawD
d’uoY .nomed tnatepmoc ytterp a m’I ,wonk
.sih teem ot ezag s’retto eht nrut dna
”…niaga em nommus ot gniyrt era sreutama nmaD“
I“ .s’aimuhtipE tsniaga keehc sih eht delzzun enyawD   .derepsihw eH
.sbur eltneg eht rednu demriuqs dna psag tfos a tuo tel eH
.daehrevo demool eh sa gniliec eht tsniaga dehctarcs ylthgil snroh s’tsaeb ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.trihs sih tuo gnihtooms ,erofeb gnittis saw eh erehw ot kcab delwarc dna pu tas ylkciuq eH ”!yrroS“
,yltfos delkcuhc eH
.mih yarteb t’ndluow ydob sih os desolc sgel sih dezeeuqs eH ”?woH-
.noisserpxe deretsulf sih edih ot gniyrt ,rood tnorf eht sdrawot dekool eH ”?hO“
”?retto elttil ,taht wonk uoY
.noitcerid tnereffid a ni mih gnillup saw mih ot thguorb nomed eht gnileef hcae ekil tlef eH
H“ .pley suovren a tuo tel
”.serised s’latrom yreve wonk I
”?uoy oD .knird uoy sselnU
.VT sih ta kool ot denrut enyawD
gnileeF“  ”!peE“ suovren a tuo tel enyawD  ”?deticxE“
,vt eht otni deppirt ,rehtegot emac teef sih sa ,dna depmuj enyawD
.retto gnilbmert won eht sdrawot pets a koot dna
.mih ediseb nomed eht fo tnemesuma eht ot ,thgiarts pu gnittis
.dnatsrednu yletelpmoc t’ndid
”!detrats gnab-gnabehs siht teg nac ew os yelhsA s’erehw ,woN“
.gnihtemos yas ot nepo htuom sih ,pu dekool eH
.dnopser t’ndluoc retto ehT
,retsaocrellor dliw a ekil saw tI
.resolc elttil a mih gnillup ,trihs s’enyawD debbarg yltneg dna drawrof denael nomed ehT
”.pu-sdaeh a desu evah dluoc I tub ,ti htiw looc ma I …ekiL
.saw nomed eht erehw ot revo dekool dna ecaf sih ffo ti dellup eH ”!yeH“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
rotinaJ motnahP ehT
.ti yojne tsuJ .ezigolopa t’noD“
,tuo sgel sih dehcterts enyawD
,esolc denael eH ”…dluoc I ebyaM“
,negahnoM selbbircS yb ”goD drawnwoD“
,delkcuhc nomed ehT
.ruf sih ekorts yltneg redluohs sih no dnah eht gnileef
.krims tfos a ni pu delruc saw elzzum eninac ehT
.ni denael eh sa erif looc a htiw denrub seye neerg s’erutaerc ehT ”.eman s’nomed A“
nomed eht gnidir saw eh
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
.daeh sih gnitlit ,aimuhtipE ta dekool enyawD
.deknilb dna ,kcab dellup enyawD
?suovren uoy ekam taht seoD“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.emahs gnimlehwrevo na gnileef
a er’uoy esuaceB“
,ylkciuq smra sih derewol dna
.seivom yracs dna agoY
,demahsa elttil a tlef eH
.yaw rehto eht dneb ot gnivom erofeb elcric a ni spih sih gnillor ylwols
.seye sih ta kool ot hctorc s’erutaerc eht morf ezag sih erot dna
.esolc mih dloh yltneg
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.hcuoc eht ot txen nwod ti gnittes dna elttob eht ffo gnihsinif ,reeb fo giws rehtona koot aimuhtipE  ”?uoy era nomed fo dnik tahW …oS“
negahnoM selbbircS yb ”goD drawnwoD“
.ssa na eb ot evah t’nod uoy ,zeeJ“
,demriuqs retto ehT ”.sknahT“
.snoihsuc hcuoc eht tsniaga ylwols gnihsiws ,tar a fo taht saw liat s’tI
.sworb sih delggiw eH ”?suoiruC
.edir krap emeht a fo daetsni
.retto roop eht esaet ot yaw rehtona ,mih morf yawa yltsom gnicaf saw nomed ehT .ezorf eH
.pal sih dettap dna
.ecaf sih no dednal htolc ytaews mraw a sa detpurretni erew sthguoht siH
– enoemos saw erehT
.esruoc fo nosaer nihtiw ,serised
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ydob sih revo hsur taeh railimaf taht gnileef ,pu ezorf enyawD
?mih htiw ti gnivael tsuj eh saW
.neercs vt sih no eye na peek llits dluoc eh os kcen sih denarc dna
pE“  ”.aimuhtipE si eman yM“
.noitnetta eht gnivol saw eH
.tniop taht ta ruoh na tuoba rof sesop rehto no gnikrow neeb ydaerla d’eH
sesicrexe agoy sih no desucof yllaitrap ylno saw eH
.lautir gnineve retteb a rof ksa t’ndluoc retto ehT
uoY”`.hcuoc eht otno kcab deppolf nomed ehT ”!tsirhC .H suseJ“
.tsehc sih ni delbmur elkcuhc s’aimuhtipE  ”–tsuj s’tI .yrros m’I-
?thgir .erofeb ereh t’nsaw tahT“
”.xes fo laeppa eht rof emac tsuj I .ereh eb ot evah t’nod I
.denworf enyawD ”t’nsi ti ,oN .oN“
neercs eht ssorca debbewredips sroloC
.llaw tnemtrapa sih tsniaga kcab llaf ti gnikam
”.ereht pu ti deen ll’I kniht t’nod I“
.niaga VT eht otni kcab delbmuts tsomla eh dna
.gniliec eht ta pu kool ot gninrut ,dennirg nomed ehT
hguoht ,elat yranoituac a siht redisnoC .ecitcarp agoy ,ssenisub ehT .enola
.naorg ypsar ,duol a htiw dehcterts dna pu doots aimuhtipE
emoh ta gnineve na ,noitautis ehT
”.enyawD s’tI“  ”.darB toN
eb ll’ti taht emussa ylno nac I os ,emoseerht a si ti naem I“
,deffuh aimuhtipE
sa elttil a nups noisiv siH
.tnemtrapa yranidro na ,ecalp ehT
.level erew secaf rieht taht os revo denael eH
.rekihhctiH flowereW ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,negahnoM selbbircS yb ”goD drawnwoD“ saw sihT       ”?tahW“
.daeh sih fo kcab eht dehctarcs eH ”?yeht era ohW“
,kcab sih dniheb smra sih dehcterts eH
.mmhM“   .tnemeticxe sih esnes ylbaborp dluoc eh wenk enyawD ,elzzum s’nomed eht no elims eht morF
.tsehc s’nomed eht tsniaga nael ot drawrof detoocs eh sa deticxe erom neve mih edam hcuot lacisyhp ehT
,renetsil ,tsniaga snoituac ti tahw
,dnuora delrihw dna thgiarts pu doots eH
,taes sih ni erom elttil a demriuqs enyawD ”.huH“  ”.esruoc
.rethgual tfos otni denrut gnilkcuhc s’nomed ehT ”.ym ho ,seY“  ”.ym hO-
.rae s’enyawD delkcit htaerb siH ”.dooG“
.trihs sih hguorht sedis s’retto eht ekorts yltneg ot sdnah sih dehcaer nomed ehT
.hcuoc eht evoba thgir toos ni nward margatnep suonimo eht ot pu derutseg eH ”.gniliec ruoy ta kool ,naem I
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehTot gninetsil er’uoY
.nekorb saw ti dna vt neercstalf llams sih ta nwod dekool eH
.tlef ton evah ew mialc nac su fo wef yrev taht raef a si ti ,erised ew tahw raef ot egnarts si ti hguohT .nwonknu si tahw raef ot elbadnatsrednu si tI .suoregnad si tahw raef ot larutan si tI  .golb rieht no egap skrow dehsilbup eht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
”?ti t’nsi ,darB si eman ruoY .oN …tiaW“
,mih ta kcab dennirg nomed eht dna ,niaga nomed eht ta kool ot denrut enyawD ”.seY“   ”.hO“
.pu dnats ot devom eh
”?tnemtrapa ym ni gniod uoy era kcuf eht tahW“
.seman eht detaeper retto ehT ”?darB ?yelhsA“
sevooh sih ot doots aimuhtipE ”?darB ,desufnoc os gnitca uoy era yhW“  ”?xeS“
.tsul dna erusaelp si emag yM .subucni na m’I“
?kcab gnimoc saw eH ”?retal em eeS“
.deretsulf ytterp llits ,yawa dekool enyawD
.decniw dna ecaf sih no htaerb toh yllamronba s’nomed eht tlef enyawD
.taorht sih ni thguac
.esop dimaryp a otni ydob reppu sih derewol eh ,thgiarts sgel sih gnipeeK
ot kcab sih ot sedis s’retto eht pu sdnah sih devom ylwols nomed ehT
.redluohs sih revo mih ta dekniw nomed ehT
”.yob dooG“   .mih gnicaf ,pal sih otni debmilc ylwols enyawD .tfos os ruf sih
.elttil a sgel sih gnidaerps yllausac
”.uoy t’nera ,yob doog
”.netfo oot enod dna nees evah I gnihtemos ton s’tahT .ycamitnI“
.enyawD ta dekool eH ”.nuf
.rae s’enyawD tsniaga htaerb toh sih gnihtaerb
,trihs sih fo og tel dna
.dnuora dekool dna thgiarts pu doots eh sa eralg latnemegduj a mih gnivig
.retto eht ot kcab deppans ezag s’nomed ehT
.tsiaw s’erutaerc eht dnuora partskcoj detnet eht deretsiger eh sa dehsulf ecaf s’retto ehT
.taht tuoba togrof I .hO“
O“ .raer sih tsniaga gnibbur kcoj detnet eht leef dluoc eh ,llet dluoc enyawD   ”.ma erus I
?tihs taht em ’niksa eb ot uoy rof noitasrevnoc eht ni etal elttil a ti
.rae s’retto eht raen detser elzzum siH
.vt eht otni detnalpecaf eh sa detnurg eH
.ylevissimsid dnah dewalc a devaw tsaeb ehT ”.llihc ,llihC“
rieht dna slatrom gniyfsitas evol I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ti devaw eh sa dehsols elttob sih ni reeb ehT ”!reeb ym ta kooL“
.tnemtrapa sih fo rood eht drawot gnicaf
.pu delbbub noisufnoc dna regna sih tub ,niaga nwod kcab kool ot detpmet saw enyawD
”?em htiw tis emoc ot tnaW“
”.em denommus ohw eno eht er’uoY“
.dnats eht no thgirpu gnittis saw ti dna
llits eH .cirbaf eht no hserf lasuora fo llems eht ,swap sih ni cirbaf eht dleh retto ehT
:yojne esaelP  .enimreted ot uoy rof si
enyawD  ”?niaga srewop ym evorp ot em tnaW“
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT ta rotide na si ohw
.mih no ezag s’nomed eht leef dluoc eh
,esolc os saw erutaerc ehT
.elbaroda gnikcuf os er’uoy ,doG“ .daeh sih evoba neht
.sehcterts sih morf nrub eht tsuj saw ti thguoht eH
.ruf nworb trohs fo osrot yriah a derevoc ssenrah A
…tsniaga gnihtyna od dluoc eh fi sa stsif otni meht gnilruc ,swap sih pu tup eH
dnim sih ni tpecxe
,nwod tis ahctnod yhW“
.rae sih morf yawa daeh sih dellup dna yltfos denaorg ylneddus eH
”?yeht era ohW …ohW“
kcab smra sih dellup aimuhtipE ”?yhs elttil a
,nwod dna pu mih gnikool seye neerg sti leef dluoc retto ehT   ”?tahW“
,pans ot dnah eerf sih desu nomed ehT ”.VT ruoy xiF“
”?nomed a yllautca er’uoY“
”.dooG-G“   ”?leef uoy od woH“
.hcuoc sih no gnittis – gnihtemos ,on
.thgiarts kcab sih htiw gnidnats saw eh os ydob reppu sih desiar enyawD
.mih dniheb delworg yltfos eciov A
.giws kciuq a koot eh dna
”.erofeb noitcaer taht dah reveN .nmaD“
?niaga mih gnisaet tsuj nomed eht saW
.elims a htiw kcab gninael
.remraw gnitteg flesmih leef dluoc eh ,hcterts sih dleh retto eht sA   .eivom eht dna enituor sih htob hsinif ot emit fo ytnelp dah eh os
ta neht ,swap sih ni partskcoj eht ta nwod dekool enyawD
,dewollaws retto ehT ”–ohW“
.tnemtrapa sih otni deklaw tsuj dah reveohw ta lley ot ydaer
neercs eht morf enog saw kcarc eht ,hguone eruS
;neercs eht no seye sih tpek enyawD
evirra ylreporp ot woh tuo erugif dluoc I kniht
.mih ediseb taes eht gnittap
namreboD a fo taht saw daeh s’erutaerc eht dnA
.delley tsomla enyawD ”?tahW“
.swap sih ni partskcoj eht ta nwod kcab dekool enyawD
si yrots s’thginoT dna
”?taht si eman a fo dnik tahW ?ai-tahw-ee-
koob eht fo rohtua eht dna
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.mih ot esolc os saw nomed eht dna ,desufnoc os saw eH
”?uoy era ohW“ !taht
.srae sih dniheb snroh devruc fo riap a htiw
”.retal uoy ees ll’I“
.sevooh nevolc fo riap a ot nwod spih sti morf nar taht ruf yvaeh ni derevoc erew sgel stI
.gniliec eht ta pu gnikool ,niaga denaorg dna dehgis aimuhtipE   ”.taht
.srebme gniwolg htiw dettod erew gniliec eht no slobmys eht sa ekoms dna taews ekil dellems ria ehT
.nomed dekan ylluf won eht
”.enyawD ,sknahT“  ”?tahw ,tiaW“
?tib eht fo trap a siht sI“  ”?uoy era ohw-W“
”.enyawD ,eman eciN“
eno siht piks esaelp
.das tib a osla tub
.esolc dellup saw eh sa nomed eht morf gnitaname taeh tfos a leef dluoc enyawD
,tuo smra sih koohs dna denaorg eH
.keehc s’retto eht gnikorts yltneg dna walc a gnikat