”.srennam toggaf taht hcaet ot thguo
”?tnalp drojF taht ot gniog er’ew em llet t’nod ,ohohO“
.tops eht no detserra teg enola tel ,enoyna dellik ro egamad suoires od t’ndid ew dedivorp ,lleW
.yltfos delims moM
.dehctaw sih dekcehc neht
.nosaes llabtoof eht ni reilrae sregakcaP eht yb depollaw teg sgniK ereiviR eht hctaw daD ot gninetsil nooccar dlo-raey-neves eht ot sknaht ,’hctib
.yawa eceip ogeL a tup t’ndid ylliB nehw ,gninrom eno
krad eht ni neve ,gniziremseM
gnidaer su tog ssikgdoH .rM retfa em ot emac ti tub
”!edud ,ti tuoba yrrow t’noD“
kcapkcab ym ni decalp dna dedracsid d’I samajap eht htaeneB  .dooG
,elpmaxe fo yaw yB  ?os od ot
.em naht rellat hcni na ylno gnidnats
,erofeb edisni toof deppets reven d’I
ni nioj sa hcum os dluoc I erofeb desuap neht
,elsI nattahnaM morf citirc tra yriaf a ekil dnuos ot toN“
.moc tod rettiwT morf
”.ecaf eht ot thgiR
.gniliaf tub dam dnuos ot tseb ym gniyrt ,mih detcerroc I
.srae dedlof htiw denaorg I ”…eniF“
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
tekcaj eidooh a dna ,snaej eulb krad
,rood eht sdrawot tfel decaf enO
derrucco tahw ot nwod emac siht rof ecnedive
hguorht yawflah ,esiarp sih evag diS
deb ot og nac uoy
,roolf delit eht derettil skram diks dna tsuD
.eciffo s’lapicnirp eht ni ruoh eno dna
.tnemugraretnuoc gnorts ylgnimussa ym deretnuoc moM
.swodniw eht ot denrut daeh yM
”?em htiw gnimoc uoY
”?tuoba taht saw tahW“  ”.lexA
,lufthgisni ylbidercni dna htiw kaeps ot suoiralih eb dluoc eH
.emocni rof tsom ti no deiler ylimaf eht fo edis s’daD no stnerapdnarg yM
?drawretfa desucxe eb I naC“
.tuo og ot ecnahc a diS dna em ekil sneet ytsgna evag ti tub
.taebtraeh enO  ”.yag m’I…m’I ?diS“
,ylhsidlihc derekcins aneyh ehT
.eno gnivil ylluf a ton tub
t’nerew ti fi thgin ta tuo gnikaens fo tniop eht eb dluow tahW
,ylf ot elba eb ll’ew ,repaer eht kcuf t’noD“
.mih htiw sdneirf tseb gnieb devol I yhw wonk ot roiretxe knup sih rednu hguone was yehT
,ereiviR ni efil gnuoy ym tuohguorht raey eht fo syad eht lla fO
”.repaer eht raef t’noD“
”?yawyna esirprus eht s’tahW“
?gnorw gnieb reven ta doog os eb ot evah syawla srehtom did yhW .nmaD  ”.ylrae
ereiviR ni reganeet dna neeterp ,buc yrevE
lufraef elttil a tsael ta
.deksa uoy ekil swodniw draykcab eht ni srab eht pu tup I ,euS ,oS“
.leets gnitsur dna retsalp llaw fo sreyal eht yb delffum
.neewollaH erofeb thgin eht od ot dennalp eh tahw diS
eno siht piks esaelp
.sdaeh rieht revo foor a evah dluoc ydobon dna serif ynam ooT
,llab suovren a otni delruc tsomla liat yM
.loohcs ruo ta skcoj eht fo emos ekil elpoep yag detah eh esuaceb
,mhtyhr-dim detcejretni eH
.strap eht gnitcepsni srekrow ro yrenihcam duol eht lla tuohtiw ,esle gnihtyna naht bmot a ekil erom demees yrotcaf ehT  ”!eruS“
.nuf gnivah krow ot tog dna
,ereiviR tsuj ton ,oN
,su esirprus ot deganam sllems luof emoS
”,ereh eb ot desoppus ton yletinifed er’ew ,yaw rehtiE“
”.naem I ,ydnaR ton ,yeoJ“
.ti od ll’I .ti pots tsuj
noitidart s’thgin eht detrats tsrif d’I ecnis stnerap ym morf neddih tpek d’I
”.em tog apdnarG skoob cimoc esoht hsinif llew sa thgim I
”...krow ta srallod xat ruO“
”.tcaf ni ,egap lanif eht yb noitaripsni htiw kcurtS
ward ot srekram tnenamrep gnisu saw fo duorp tlef I tnemeveihca enO .’enoB seeyolpmE‘
thgis eht fo llif ruo dah I dna eH
,dedecnoc I ”.tniop riaF“
,elims suoiruc ,yls a htiw detcejretni diS ”,tsriF“
.erif no retspmud a tes yllatnedicca dna stekcor yluJ fo htruoF detset aneyh eht nehw ,1991 ni thgiN s’liveD saw nosra dehcaorppa reve ti tsesolc ehT .ton ro tnacav ,esuoh a gnihcrot sa raf sa tnew reven I dna diS  ”.sdaeh
.mih ta rae lacizziuq dna
.yab gnidaol eht raen elip egral a ni dniheb tfel srebbur tleb reyevnoC
”…ybab nom’C“ ,llewriats etercnoc eht nwod dna pu deohce sdrow ruo sa mih htiw ni denioj I
.tnalp drojF eht tuoba hguone wenk I tub
worbeye na desiar I  ”.ebyam…“
tnellecxe dah saneyh dna snooccar doG knahT
”?teertS ht01 no yrotcaf otua taht rebmemer os ,spoc htiw dellif eb lliw etuor ruo syas teerts eht no droW“
”!lexA ,duorp olegnalehciM ekam dluow uoY“
.em no denwad ti erom eht ,ti ta derats I erom ehT
.yluJ raen skrowerif ro remmus ni stekcirc naht yltnereffid on draeh eb dluoc sneriS
.gnitnuah eht od taht ssenkrad eht ni sgniht eht tuoba tsuj t’nera sedaf rebotcO eht sa syad detnuah eht ,esruoc fO
”.ssa uoy ,eltit lluf eht dias uoy taht tnaem I“
.niaga desuap diS
,seohs ruo rednu sessalg fo sdrahs
ytinutroppo tcefrep eht ti deredisnoc I ?eM
”,repaer eht kcuf t’nod
.ecaps llaw knalb a revo lla
.esirprus a saw ti demialc eH
.gnihtemos uoy wohs nac I os ereh uoy thguorb I tub“
”,era yeht ekil eb nac eW“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.pets hcae pu dnuow ew sa em fo daeha gnikrims
.naelc deppirts skcart ylbmessA
?sgurd ti sI“ .depsag kcom I
.niveK dna yellehS did oS
.hcaeb eht ta gnimmiws ro gnikib remmus fo yad tsal eht dneps ot detnaw rehtar sdik rehto eht fo tsom erehw ytrap a dah reven I dna eH
.snoitcnujnoc ekil sdrow esruc gniws t’ndid eh nehw ynapmoc sih dekil wohemos stnerap yM
”,dlrow eht morf sevlesruo edih ot ekil ew hcum woh dna
”.rewomnwal wen a deen ll’ew tuo dnif dna worromot neewollaH no pu ekaw ot tnaw t’noD
.diS dniheb yltcerid dewollof I dna
,kcid sih gnikcus neeb s’ydnaR enoyreve gnillet
.nirg neddih a gniyrrac mih ot denrut dna mih ta rae na dekrep I ”,tiaW .ahctoG“  ”.ereh dnuora tihs sotsebsa taht fo yna ni gnihtaerb ay deen t’nod I .t’noD“
.noisnet yna esae ot ’omoh on‘
.ecils rehtona ni ti decils I sa eloressac eht fo mottob eht ta deparcs krof yM
.sthgif lacisyhp otni tog reven eh tub
eno ta mlif ydemoc etihw-dna-kcalb a rof gnineercs thgindim a ni mih nioj ot em decnivnoc diS
”.emit siht nossel ym denraeL“
”.hsac ni gnillor eb t’now I
,neeb evah tsum ereiviR ralucatceps woh enigami dluoc I
a ni pu em dellup eH
’tihs yssup‘ dna
.htaerb fo ekatni prahs A .staebtraeh owT
.4991 ,ht03 rebotcO saw etad ehT  .thgiN s’liveD no
.eciffo ralugnatcer ytpme na ot rood eht gninepo elihw dekoj eH
”!ris doog ,taht ot esneffo ekat I“
.stnecs eht fo tsom tuo dekcolb selzzum ruo revo sanadnab eht ,yllufknahT
”!etatse laer eerf s’tI !lexA ,esruoc fO“
,selttob reeb nekorB
.worbeye na desiar I
,eno rof tey wonk t’ndid eH
”?wonk’y ,rehtom nmad ruoy ekil gnidnuos er’uoy ,tihS
”.repaer eht kcuf t’noD“
”.oot srewsna dna snoitseuq emaS
.lla dna ereht tuo gninrub s’ti hcum woh eeS
,em ta nwod detnap eh sa nirg siH
.nwotnwod ni sretaeht dnarb-ffo erom eht fo
”?ti dluow ,hguoht elbat ym no doof tup pleh yltcaxe t’noW“
.revadac a saw eloressac anut fo ecils sih dna leplacs a saw efink citsalp sih dedneterp ylliB elihw ,naorg a desserppus elbat eht ta ydobyrevE
.daor eht no ettevroC wen-dnarb a ekil em tih ot noitseuq lacirotehr sih rof ylno ,deksa I
eht yb deluah saw diS nehw airetefac eht ta devirra d’I ,detnarG  ”?od eh did tahW“
”?esaelp ,esaelp ,esaelP“ ,dedaelp araM
,em rof enitolliug eht ro shtnom ruof rehtie eb ll’ti neht ,esneffo rehtonA
.eciov sih ni emityad eht sa raelc niadsid
,etib eno ni ecils sih fo lluf krof a dewollaws daD ”.em toN“
,tnalp drojF dlo eht
.spil ym morf delbbub hgual suoixna nA
.yaw tcerroc eht nrow ylgnisirprus
,hgual a kcab deffocs eH
,enil lanogaid a ot sknaht eip a emaceb ngis gnikoms on a no lobmys etteragic ehT
.shtaerb peed fo spuccih neewteb delggig I ”?ti t’nia
.sllaw daed sti nihtiw etalumucca ot gniunitnoc tpek itiffarg yldlrowrehto dna hsart tey
”.lexA ,tfel ruoy ot kool woN
?raey tsal ssalc yrtsimehC morF
,yks emitthgin sselduolc a htaenrednu foor krad a laever ot denepo tI  ”!rood eht s’ereh
.hcnul erofeb nwalegnarO dna gnimoyW no serif ylrae emos erew ereht raeh I“
”?raey yreve seod ehs ekiL“
ssenkrad eht ni dekrims diS
.eciffo s’reganam gnirob ,yffuts a eb ot desu tahw fo llaw kcab eht pu edam ti fo llA
,potfoor levarg eht fo egde eht morf trapa teef lareves deppets I
”—rotut a teg uoy pleh ot mom ym ecnivnoc dna stnerap ym ot klat nac I
”.thgiN s’liveD dna thgin loohcs a s’tI“
.skcap etteragic ytpme dna ,stlob ,stun revotfel fo ytnelp
.oot srab htiw dettiftuo spohs llams eht fo emos ,swodniw derettuhs eht noitnem ot toN
.ecneibma edistuo yb neddih naom gnilbmur siH  2 fo
ekil erom og annog saw I“
.gnos railimaf a gnimmuh yb em dekoops diS ,llewriats kcalb-hctip eht pu yaw ruo nO
,gnis ylwol ot nageb eh ”,dniw eht od ron
reh gnilennahc em fo duorp eb d’ehs wenk osla I .wenk I
.gniroolf nepo-ediw fo esnapxe krad ,ytpme nA
”?niaga tsaeB eht & ytuaeB hctaw ew naC“
,denoitnem eh ,nwod anadnab ym dellup tsomla I nehW
.gnilggig pots t’ndluoc I tub ,redluohs eht no kcams hsrah a flesym denrae I
,sttub etteragic ,selttob nekorB
,toggaf a mih gnillac ,namhserf ome siht no gnikcip saw eH“
nees eb ot mehyam eht ni detnioppasid eb t’ndluow I esimorp did aneyH eht hguohT
,tnecca hsitirB hsop a ni em ta delrans yllufyalp eH
tloj A  ”!gaf ,flow a ot em gnirapmoc rof s’tahT“
.ecnadnetta roop etipsed
,esuoh s’nifareS diS ta thgin eht dneps I naC ?daD ?moM“
.sruoh ekil yb dessap setuniM
”.t’nseod boj s’daD
.hcni na egdub t’ndluow eh tub
,nwot tsohg a toN .nwot esotamoc a
,sicoV sumoD yb
”.ssabmud suoethgir-fles a gnieb saw yeoJ“
,thgis eht ta deltsihw diS
”.oot eM“  .aneyh a
,srehcaet ruo yb knup a sa detnuoc ylniatrec dna htuom a dah evah thgim eH
,deb ot ffo tnew yeht dna noziroh eht no dnecsed ot nageb ksud sa noos sA
”?xelA ,krowemoh ruoy hsinif uoY“
,ksud eht hguorht thgiltops a naht thgirb yna neeb evah ton dluoc elims siH
.rewsna eht wenk ydaerla I
.8102 ni
.eloressac fo tib mraw a otno puhctek emos depoocs I sa deggurhs I
.diS htiw kcab sraey wef a
.knurd yllaicepsE“  ”?knurd dnA“
,secalp lla fo tnalp rac eht ot og ot detnaw eh yhw tuo erugif ot gniyrt
.emitgnirps ni srewolf retteb evah dluow nedrag draykcab s’moM tsael tA
.kcab sraey elpuoc a
,’gaf‘ dnuora worht yllausac t’ndid eh ,diS ot tub
.tuo eb ot suoregnad oot s’thginoT“
”.thginot ereh eb ot desoppus neve ton er’ew ,nom’C“ .delahni ylprahs aneyh ehT
,sllaw dedderhs eht morf dekculp sepip dna gniriW
”.drah taht t’nsaw ti ,haeY“
.guh edis ruo morf yawa flesmih dehsup dna deffocs aneyh ehT ”.edud ,revetahW“
,htiw detcerroc dna elzzum sih koohs eH
.thgin taht knurd t’nsaw daD yM“
,roolf dnuorg etalosed eht no nwod gnikool htoob desolcne ,egral a ot pu gnidael eno eht saw tI
ydobemos dediced I dna
”?taht no llac eht pu kcip uoy diD
.eceip eno ni llits s’ti tsirhC knahT
”.noitcerid rehto eht s’etuor lamron ruO“ .mih deksa I
.noissergga deganeet
,’yadot ereh eb ot desoppus neve ton m’I‘ s’tI“
.thgiN s’liveD tuoba gnihtyreve tsomla dootsrednu ,dlrow eht neve dna nagihciM fo tser eht
,tuons sih revo anadnab kcalb a pu dellup yltneuqesbus diS
,raef t’nod snosaeS“
,nisnocsiW fo sretniw citcrA eht gnivarb ton s’eh nehw noitcifnaf dab gnidaer emit sih sdneps ohw ,sicoV sumoD yb
”.retsim ,diS htiw pu teem ot yadrutaS dna yadirF fo lla dah uoY“  ”.nuh ,yrroS“
”.tcefrep s’ydoboN“
em llac ot mih teg ot deirt d’I ,sraey roF(  ”!lexA !iO“
.ylthgils dedlof srae ym fo enO .mih deksa I
.tfola foor hcrop sih gnidloh snmuloc nedoow deitiffarg eht fo eno tsniaga gnidnats ,mih dettops I erehT
.em desimorp eh ,niaga reveN
.dnuora gnikool peek s’teL“
”!era ew naht loohcs eht ot resolc yllaretil s’diS“
”—uoy rof esirprus a tog I sulp
,raews I  ”.tsirhC knahT“
’yssis‘ ro ’yssup‘ ,’toggaf‘
.ecnatsid eht ni serif fo rebmun lausunu eht ta epaga derats I sa spil ym morf llef sdrow ehT ”…yloH“
,diS morf yawa toof elgnis a tfird ton did I ,emit eritne ehT
”?yadsendeW tsal rebmemer uoy
,yrotcaf trap rac denmednoc eht gnikoolrevo ylno ton
”?siht no gnikrow neeb uoy evah gnol woh ,diS“
”.ereht nuf hcum os evah d’uoY
,su ot pu thgir thguac staebtraeh ruo sa tnatsid werg tI
.htaeneb trihs retaeb efiw dezisrevo na dna ti htaeneb emarf ralucsum eht gnithgilhgih ,thgiN s’liveD yreve raew d’eh tekcaj krad derettat-imes eht no dennip erew snottub etairporppani dna lacitilop fo snezoD
,nageb lla ti woh ro yhw wenk ydoboN
”.yadretsey hsub fo tuo nar I
nevig erew serugif kcits
rof thgiN s’liveD no tuo tnew I dna diS  ”!pu tihs emos raet dna elohekup gnikcuf siht attuo teg s’teL“ .ekoms fo wollib tnatsid a dna sneris eht fo ecruos eht sdrawot gnidael daor tnecajda na nwod elzzum deroloc-itlum sih denoitom eH ”!neht nom’C“
”,noitidart a s’tI“
.espylacopa na fo tuo thgiarts dellup neeb d’ti ekil dekool weiv ehT
yas yldednahffo ro
.tnemhsinotsa ni depsag yletaidemmi dna ,os did I
”.dnah ym ekat ,ybaB“
,hcnul ,llah yduts ym dnepS
.nemodba ym no wap mraw A .sdniw gnilwoH
,daeh sih koohs eH
”.sruoy fo ’esirprus‘ siht ot yaw eht dael uoY“
.krowemoh s’keew tsal su evag dna ekatsim a edam rehcaet etutitsbus eht os
.gnitnuah eht evarb ohw elpoep eht tuoba era yehT .detnuah si taht
.renroc rehtona denrut eW
.ytilauxesomoh detesolc ym ot gnirrefer saw eh kniht ot ton ydob ym dednimer ssensuoicsnoc yM
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
***  ”.laed a flesruoy tog uoy dna sehsid eht yrd em pleH“
esaeler ot ecnahc a su evag tI
niaga ,eloressac anut—
.tahwemos dexaler I litnu ,ezeerf em edam ylfeirb
.pots ot desufer sdrow eht tey
”.enob ynnuf eht tih tsuj uoy kniht I“
em neewteb gnitniuqs ,rae ot rae dennirg diS
.seitiliba lagelarap
.moorkaerb s’rekrow eht ro eciffo s’reganam eht rehtie morf tuo deggard ylekil hcuoc lautca nA
,thgilf txen ruo deunitnoc ew sa deggurhs I ”.em ot ton
,namelbon citarcotsira na naht seltaeB eht ot nika erom
.mrahc a ekil dekroW
.ti hsid ot denrut diS nehw
,rood eht morf yawa
.liat nooccar yhsub ym pu dna enips ym nwod thgir tperc llihc A
,kcoc erab ym dnuora gnisserac sregnif ylnaM
.diS ,raey txen sTAS eht retfa ti redisnoc ot thguo uoY“
,noziroh eht gnola gnigar dna gnicnad sonrefni eht dnoyeB
,ecnef eht ni eloh neddih a hguorht em gnidiug retfA
tahw oS“ ,ksa ot dediced I ,tnemom teiuq rehtona retfA
,eninac llat eht ta krims ot yawa ti koohs tub ylper ym ni detatiseh tsomla I
.redluohs eht ni em gnikcin yb dednopser eH
,krow llarevo ruo ta tnemtnetnoc ni dehgis eh
?lairetam egelloc toN ?ebyaM“
deksa dna oga sraey gnineve eno derob tog tsuj I ?eM
.mih ta tuo eugnot ym kcuts dna
,ewa ni duola desum eH
”.em ot lleH otni wodniw a ekil sdnuoS“
.keew suoiverp eht
,fo kniht nac I egelloc tra ’nikcuf tseb eht rof pu ngis ll’I .enif ,enif ,eniF“ ,denaorg eH
,sesuoh detalupop ,seirotcaf gniviL
,sroloc gnag ta stpmetta ni dekced ,sriats ycnegreme eht dnuof eW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”!edud ,dias ehs tahw s’tahT !aH“
”?lexA ,taht no em ffir annog llits uoY“
.delkcuhc I ”,neht ythgirlA“
,era ew tahw ,era ew ohW“ .denialpxe eh
”thgiN s’liveD no gnicnaD“   yojne esaelP
,ecaps nepo eht fo noitces a gnikoolrevo eciffo s’reganam eht ot em gnidiug tnew diS erofeB
eht‘ tuoba dionarap elttil a fi
”?neht thgin yb flow suoredrum ,trohs a er’uoy taht neht gniyas uoy erA“
,rebotcO-dim ni reilrae skeew elpuoc a tsuJ
,edir sub eht no em dlot yltnulb aneyh gnilkcac ehT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”…won siht was srehcaet tra ruo ylno fI“
.roolf yrotcaf denodnaba eht ta nwod deralg wodniw ssalg ytrid a elihw
.foor gnitsur a htaenrednu ria looc eht ni gnizeerf
.eninac a ekil depahs t’nerew setteuohlis ehT
.yadnuS yzal rehtona tsuJ
ym ta ecneserp siH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
”?dren a ekil ti daer I tahT“
od…uoy od ,hcihw fo gnikaepS“
:yadhtrib emas eht derahs ew ,eno roF
.sriatspu krowemoh yrtemonogirt ym dehsinif I dna
.swodahs rolocinhcet ehT .swobniar ehT
,kcapkcab ym morf meht detsuahxe I emit eht yB
.esolc erew ew tub
,hE“  ”?ivoJ noB lavir d’ti knihT“
,oot anadnab a fo eldnub a em dessot eH
”.etsaw a neeb lla evah d’ti esle rO
,ytinummoc gniworg fo esnes a dna ,sklawedis demoorg-llew
.foor eht ees og annaw I“
.yerg thgil saw ti ylno
.kcab ym gnittap ,hgual aneyh kramedart sih delkcac diS
—gnitaeb eht semoc ereh ,kniht I
.neewollaH erofeb evael reh stel boj reh
.sllaw etercnoc eht otno dellird llits sngis sgninraw yna no srettel gnicafed dedulcni elpmaxe enO
,ytinutroppo rehtona gnidnif ton denigami I nehT
.ylthgil gnilkcuhc ,rae suovren a fo kcab eht dehctarcs I
.degnahc eb t’ndluoc dna pu edam saw dnim reh revenehw dlot ehs drow ehT .’doirep‘
.ydob dinac sih edisni gniliob syawla enoretsotset dna noissergga pu-tnep eht esaeler ot tuo tnew eH
.elttob a no deppirt tsomla gnivah
”.orb ,omoh oN“
.drowraews rehtona denrael ylekil evah dluow ylliB dna araM esle ro ,emit ni tsuj taorht reh deraelc moM
.resiw eht gnieb ydobyna tuohtiw rood kcab eht tuo dekaens dna moorhtab eht ot og ot dedneterp I
,mih htiw snoitseuQ 02 gniyalp deirt I
,loohcs ta sbulc ro seuqilc emas eht ni t’nerew nifareS diS dna eM
,latem fo egde prahs a morf kcapkcab ym kcutsnu pleh ot gnisuap
…mih llet…mih llet ot
.reeb sih fo spis neewteb derettum daD
,noitasrevnoc lausac ni sdrow evisneffo ,tnulb esu ot mih desuac retlif renni na fo kcal siH
.hgis peed a dah dna deppiuq eH
”.eciov gnignis a tog uoy ,eil annog toN !wO“
.edis tsew s’ereiviR ot repeed gnidael klawedis dekcarc eht gnola rac gnihcaorppa yna fo yraw dna seot ym no kciuq eb ot em gnitpmorp ,sesuoh detadipalid fo swor dna swor eht revo sneris tnatsid raeh ydaerla dluoc I
.ylimaf eht ni gnar repeels yvaeh a gnieb doG knahT
.ereht ti edam ew nehw
.taht ekil ti ebircsed nac drow rehto oN .gniziremseM
.noisiv thgin
.syaw larutannu ni trapa nrot ro tneb stenibac gnilif lareveS
”thgiN s’liveD no gnicnaD“
)eb ot ti detnaw I sa dilos sa ton( yM
.sedulretni trohs neewteb deirav eunev s’thgin eht ot esuoh sih morf snoitasrevnoc ruO
.citehtapme eb ot gniganam elihw ,’tnemhsilbatsE
”…niar eht ro nus eht“
”.t’nera ew nehw eb ot yrt ew tahw
”…no gniog sderdnuh eb
”.T a ot nwod taorht ruoy fo kcab eht ni hctip taht tog uoy esuaceb ,wonk’Y .nosnhoJ nairB
,yltcerroc rebmemer I fI“
rennid rof nwod em dellac stnerap yM
,dias diS ekil dna
,yadot ni t’nsaw snommisztiF .rM“
.II raW dlroW-tsop emit a nopu ecno
.emerpus dengier msiladnav dna yhcrana elihw nrub
,emit eht dna ,ecalp eht tuoba era yehT
,haN“  ”!sgurd s’ti em lleT
.dluoc eh reverehw sevael top wolley-dna-neerg gnitniap yarps
.daeh sih dniheb pu ti gniyt
,meh sih yb mih sllup llub eht
).relooc dnuos em edam ti ,sulP
”.deraeppa ecnef eht ni eloh taht ecniS“
.ereht nuf evah d’uoy wonk uoy dna ,tsitra citsatnaf a er’uoy taht s’ti
,)srekram tnenamrep dna repap teliot fo sllor lareves rof evas sgniht lla fo deitpme(
,gniugraretnuoc yb koob s’rehtom ym morf egap a koot hguoht
.sehsid eht hsaw pleh ot deksa eb ot deen neve t’ndid diS
.setalp ruo otno secils depoocs ehs sa deksa moM ”?nuh ,krow saw woH“
,gnihtyna wonk I fi ,diS
,gniohce na detuohs neht ,dehgual I ”!gnizama si sihT“
”.thgin lla evah t’nod eW
.’edyH .rM dna llykeJ .rD fo esaC egnartS ehT‘
”!ebab ,thgiN s’liveD“
.niaga mih ees em tel reven d’yeht ,nehT
,tih noissecer eht erofeb tsuj adirolF ni odnoc a ot deriter yeht retfA
”.raey tsal ekil yawa em sesahc daD ruoy erofeb elohekup siht evael s’tel ,oS“
,eninac rehto eht ,elihwnaeM
.diS dna xelA rof tuo yalp lliw thgiN s’liveD fo tser eht woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.redrah elttil a efink eht tsiwt ot dediced I
,goD fo ecioV ehT eht no
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
”…dna gnirps dna ni nwod desolc tI ?ti tuoba tahw ,haeY“
,ti otni troffe tup eh nehw tneduts taerg a tub ,tneduts doog a tsuj ton saw aneyh eht gniwonk ydaerlA
,nehT .deppord nip a
”.oot mih ta deffim tog snairotcidelav eht llA .syasse koob rieht no ’edyH dna llykeJ‘ dah ylno ohw enoyreve rof stniop ffo koot ssikgdoH
.ffo mih deppilf I tub ,ti ees t’ndid ylekil eH
,yna dednetta reve eh taht ton
redluohs eht ni epiws thgil a em denrae nup tahT
,noitcerid rehtona ni bmuht sih gnibbaj erofeb delkcac eH
.llaw eciffo eht gninroda eceipretsam eht dna mih neewteb seye ediw htiw derats I
.krims a emaceb nworf detpmetta yM
.shtnom owt rof noisnepsus loohcs-nI“
”?diS ,emit siht gniog ew erehW“
?sgruB eitrA rebmemeR“
,edarg driht ni kcab eman ym daersim eh ecnis reve ,xelA
”—a s’ruf emos pu thgir kcuts s’gnihtemos
,ylenani deggurhs I  ”?dedulcni uoY“
.tnalp eht fo tsew gnitpure serif eht ot ylralucitrap
.detneler reven eh tub
.gniliec eht ni smaeb desopxe eht revo sllor repap teliot gnissot ni em gnitsissa yb tuo em depleh ylregae diS
:noitanitsed ruo ot su del yllautneve sgoj dehsuh dna gniklaw decap-tsaF
”?I t’ndid ,taht devresed I“
.hcnul gnirud notrelluC yeoJ gnipollaw uoy was I“  ”?yadsendeW tsaL“
.llac eht tog hcivodaR yeoJ .yeoJ“
.thgiN s’liveD tuoba wenk
.em ot decnalg ylwols diS
.gnisuoh laitnediser s’ereiviR fo tser eht htiw degalfuomac taht krap lairtsudni decnef knil-niahc evisnapxe na
.tfel prahs a edam ew dna
,epat tsaeB eht & ytuaeB taht fo gniweiv htnet reh hguorht yawdim RCV s’moor ylimaf eht desuap araM retsis elttil ym sa—
,llaw kcab eht fo yteritne eht pu gnikaM
mraw tsehc ym gnikam
.ycnegreme lautca na s’ereht sselnu 119 llac ot ton rellac knarp a gnillet ma I ereht ,elihwnaeM
sallertsE saL ni stoir esoht htiw deneppah ti draeh I“
.yawa sesuoh lareves erehwemos tuo deralb neris s’rac ecilop A
”?daerps lliw meht fo yna kniht uoy oD“
,wodniw nepo na morf gnimoc dniw eht htiw deyaws sretceps etihw llat fo egnar ediw a
.ti noitnem t’ndid eh ro ,tahT
,yawa selim morf sneris gnihceercs dna stuohs tnatsiD
,yrtemonogirt htiw selggurts llits eh ,tegrof t’noD“
.spil sih gnikcil
dluow ytic eht ssorca sesuoh tnacav nehw neewollaH erofeb thgin ehT
.regnol tib a detiaw evah dluoc I
ailatineg deliated
.snosaer tnereffid
:si ti tahw otni ytic ruo edam snosra dna syaweerf eht neht tub
.ti dnuora gnieotpit yldrawkwa neeb dah diS dna em ,tnedicni eht ecnis revE  ”…yako-o ,hA“
,retniw hcae yawa detsur roiretxe ehT
,kcab thgir tlusni na sweps ydnaR elttil ,yawynA
.rethgual ym ni gninioj yllanif litnu derekcins/gnas eh
,levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
.oot dekcol s’dehs ehT
,kconk ot ton uoy dloT
”…no gniog erif a sah ni sevil eh krap reliart taht kniht I
,dibrof doG ro gnibbats a ro gnitoohs a ekiL
delevram ew sa deksa diS
.em ot emac retal ro renoos sdrow ehT ”…siht ,woW…ahW“
,noihsaf lufroloc ni devirra derewsna siH
1 traP ,sicoV sumoD yb
.gnidliub niam eht ot su detolip dna
.esle ydobyreve rof etatse laer eerf emaceb ti
gnikcuf‘ ,yas ot woh wenk ydaerla ylliB
,eurt demrifnoc ydaerla erew lareneg ni slauxesomoh no ecnats s’diS tuoba snoicipsus yM
.em fo tuo elggig a teg ot tsuj enil etirovaf ym ecnerefer d’eh tniop eht ot
.duola desum daD ”,tniop dilaV“
.em deracs reven roiretxe ecaf-ruoy-ni ffurg siH
”?siht ekam ot uoy tog
”.eciffo s’reganam eht ni s’tI
.yrc ot esuom eht gnitteg
.gnihgual dna gnihgual
”.em tuoba erac od uoY .esuaP“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,srekaens kcalb motsuc ym erew em no dah I sehtolc eht
,rufdaeh deyd-kcalb s’aneyh tliub-llew ehT
”?egelloc tra ot gniog no nalp uoY“
”!ereh er’uoy ,lexA“  .dray tnorf tpmeknu s’esuoh eht morf em ot pu nar eh dna
.guh edis a otni em gnillup ,redluohs ym kcab eht deppals diS ”!si ti A ’nikcuF“  ”!gnizamA“
”.oot .P.U eht ni ylimaf gnitisiv s’mom ym ykcul eB“
”.gnissapsert elihw hgih gnitteg kcul dab s’ti ,sediseB“
?uoy od ,boj taebdaed a ni pu dne annaw t’nod uoy ,revewoH“
.sedis citsitra…ruo
,yad a sruoh evlewt rof yawa gnivals dna ,seirotcaf ni gnikroW
.6791 ,ts13 tsuguA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
goD fo tsohG ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.dub ,did erus uoY“  ”?I t’ndid
.mih ta ylralucitrap ,su ta deralg ehs kool ytrid eht morf ylthgils knarhs htob eW
,hguoht ytilaud tuoba gnikniht em tog tI“
gnisserpxe ni mih denioj I
noitneted ot tekcit tnatsni na naem t’ndid ti fi ytirohtua fo srebmem detcepser ylno eH .sdrow
?I t’ndid ,thgin taht rood eht no kconk ot ton uoy dloT
.kcab-ot-kcab doots setteuohlis eninac owt
”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“
nem ylimaf ssalc-gnikrow fo sderdnuh yolpme depleh ecalp eht ,sraey roF
.sdoohrobhgien ruo dnuora
.sniatruc dedderhs ekil gniliec eht morf gnilgnad
”…repaer eht raef t’noD…ybab nom’C“
.nwot elohekup ruo fo tser eht tub
seno tseb eht fo eno ti edam ytrap yadhtrib hthgie
gnihton rof thgiN s’liveD ti llac t’nod yehT“
,sediseb dna“ ,deugra eh
,hcamots ym gnidloh em dah ylneddus gnos eht ot noitidda s’diS
.em fo retteb eht tog ytisoiruC
”?lexA ,siht fo kniht ahctahw ,oS“
,ylimaf eht htiw eivom SHV a ro VT hctaw ot tnaw t’nod uoy fI
”…ylf ot elba eb ll’eW“
.tniop-no dna tnulb em derewsna moM ”.t’nac uoY .epoN“  ”?esaelp
.wam deretlifnu sih morf sdrow eht raeh ot dedeen I tub
.esirprus yb seuqilc eht fo emos thguac tI
yas dluoc ehs erofeb deugraretnuoc I
.emitliaj ro noislupxe ,esrow ro
.savnac sih otni edam eh retsalp llaw eht dna
”.htraE no lleH ekil skool ti sselnu
tuohguorht eivom suoiralih eht ta gniwaffug pots t’ndluoc eH
raef cirtcele fo
.smret esrow hcum ytic gnidnuorrus eht dna emoh sih dellac yltsenoh d’eH
.bmilc eht deunitnoc ew ,secruos rieht dnif naht rehtar tub
.aremac a thguorb d’I hsiw em edam siht ekil stnemoM
.srepparcs etarepsed yb ylekil
srood sti desolc tnalp eht
,edisa nac reeb sih gnittes ,laem sih otni kcab gud eh sa ylsuovren delkcuhc daD ”,yawynA“
”.krowemoh s’keew tsal od neve t’ndid eh dna
.ereh pu uoy thguorb I emit eht yb pu ti kcuf ot owt ro knup rehto emos detcepxe-flah I ,tsenoh eb oT“
.esacriats etercnoc eht fo noitcerid eht ni em gnillup detrats eh
.elbat nehctik eht no swoble ym tup I nehw em ot kool ytrid a evag ehS
.pot eht ot yaw eht lla gnidael
.ecitcarp dedeen osla mra gniworht yM
.pihsdneirf gnol-edaced ruo dekraps osla tI
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.esuoh sih ot yaw eht gnola dessim eb ton dluoc snac tniap yarps deitpme dna ,noitavlas gnihcaerp telhpmap deiddum a
,yadirF ecnis degnahcnu
,yawyna revoekam elttil a ti evig ot thguo ew ekil gnileef neeb ev’I“
.hctiwt liat yhsub ym dna
,drawthgir derats ,srekram tnenamrep tneps fo snezod eb ot deraeppa tahw yb depahs
?yeht era ,ereiviR ni hsac ni gnillor t’nera stsitra gniggaT“
.snaej nrot sih morf dekeep srexob der sa pih tfel sih gnola delgnad sniahc tleB
?erofeb ti deciton evah I t’ndluoc woH
”.eheh ,omoh oN“ ,dedda ylkciuq dna og em tel neht ,guh orb gib
”?tnelat nwo ym ffo gniwohs sediseB“
otni denrut ’ylnO seeyolpmE‘ ,skcid evissam
seye ym dellor I hcihw ot ,deksa eh
.retsalp egieb eht otni dellicnep yllaretil
delbmeser erom yehT
”.gnisirprus s’taht woN“
,rennid rof esuoh ym detisiv netfo eh nehW
.siht ekil ecalp a ni uoy ekil enoemos enigami t’nac I
ytinigriv ym esol ot detcepxe reven I
”thgiN s’liveD no gnicnaD“
”…enil eht no k104 a htiw boj eciffo yffuts a ro
.moC tod rettiwT morf ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer
.gniod erew ew tahw wenk sklof ym ylno fI  .ti did tsuj eH
,moor sih ot ylliB gnidnes dna meht htiw araM gnignirb
.ot gnirrefer saw eh aera eht tuo ekam tsuj dluoc I
.tniap yarps fo dellems taht wobniar rolocinhcet a sdrawot
.emoc modgnik ot roiretni eht dehsart ydaerla elpoep fo ytnelp dna sraey evif ylno desolC  .roiretni eht ta
:taht ylpmis sa meht gniees dna
,yldesuma eugnot sih dekcilc eH
.loohcs eht ot gnidael euneva eht ot tnecajda dna seirotcaf rac dlo eht tsap ,esuoh ym morf os ro skcolb thgie doog a detser ecalp s’diS
.dessefnoc eh ”,peY“
,etoyoC triD yb daeR  .noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif osla nac uoY
.ees yltcefrep dluoc I erehw
pac llabesab gnittif-rae na ni derevoc saw
.esnopser sih ni desuap eH  ”?diS“ .deksa I
,deksa yletaidemmi dna
attog s’erehT ?huh ,ereht tuo ti ta gniog yllaer er’yeht ,nmaddoG“
,I dluoc rehtien dna
dael fo edam ssenkrad hctip ta gnikool ruf lufroloc a
.eceipretsam elbamuserp sih ta gnilevram ni denioj dna em ot txen deppets eH
’timmaddog‘ ,yas ot woh denrael araM
,teprac eht no elzzup detelpmoc-flah sih desuap ylliB
”.repaer eht raef t’noD“
.tsol teg dna ffo rednaw ylisae dluoc I gniwonk
.efil rof em dnuorg naht erom od dluow stnerap ym ,esiwrehtO
,lexA yeH !era ew erehT“
.pu thgil noisserpxe sih edam elkcuhc llams A
.teerts tnacav eht no doots I erehw morf no nrut t’ndid sriatspu sthgil ehT