,ylleb s’yrevA dettep kcirreD
,mooregnahc eht naht rethgirb ylthgils
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
belaC otni sregnif sih gud eH
.egdub t’ndid rood eht tuB .deraor yeht dna
.pots ot ti detnaw reven eh dna erom yna eldnah t’ndluoc kcirreD
”,myg eht ot daeh dna ihsus fo dnuor siht hsinif s'tel nehT" ?thgir
”eoR tnorF“   :yojne esaelP
”,tuo tsehc dna kcab ttuB“
.kcab rab eht tup dna
,kcen sih ot sgel sih morf
.derepmihw kcirreD dna
.mih edisni dils kcoc s’yrevA dna
,ssa sih tsniaga desserp spih s’yrevA nehT
,tuo tsehc ,kcab ttuB
.hguone riaF“ .dehgis belaC
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ffo deliart neht ,dias kcirreD ”…I“
,edis eht ot daeh sih detsiwt
.deksa belaC ”?KO uoY“
.dessap gnileef eht ,ylwolS
”.hcneb eht no mih pots t’now uoY“
.drah kcirreD depmup dna ,erom ecno kcoc s’kcirreD depsarg knurt siH
.mih derehtoms dah gav dna ylleb s’belaC tub hgual ot deirt kcirreD .knurt s’belaC .dekcus dna—
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
eh taht rednimer a
”!yddaD ,ereht uoy tog s’eH“
!worrub eritne ruoy tauqs dluoc I
".spuos osim eerht dna ,sgnilpmud ufot evlewt ,emamade fo setalp ruof ,sdalas deewaes xis …ekil sllemS
.sleeh sih hguorht dehsup eH
”,orp a ekil evacnam ym eta uoy dnA“
.aes peed eht fo detsat dna eugnot sih no etaciled saw eor ehT
.myg eht doolf t’ndid ti desirprus saw eh
.deffins dna ria eht otni esor knurt s’belaC
.mp9-ma6 :sruoH ylimaF“
,emit tsal eno dehtaerb
,dias belaC ,mooregnahc eht ot deklaw yeht sA
detnaw kcirreD tub ,denrub sgnul sih dna ,deniarts selcsum sih ,woN
.ecaf sih otni knas
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.tsrif ffo belaC teg ot gniog t’nerew eh fi denmad eb d’eh tub ,esolc gnitteg saw kcirreD
,daer taht ngis a dleh srood eht fo enO
,repeed flesmih dellup dna ssa s’belaC debbarg eh ,daetsnI
.kcoc s’kcirreD dnuora gniredduhs knurt sih ,deraor belaC
,tuo dellup yrevA nehT
.htrof dna kcab dekorts dna strohs sih nwod enog dah dnah s’yrevA
.ylleb rieht dekcams yrevA  .derats kcirreD
,deretne eerht eht sa koohs dnuorg eht nehw tub
"?taht ekiL" .dias belaC
”?neht ,pihsrelaed eht ot kcaB“
.rab eht detfil kcirreD
.tuo tsehc rieht sehsup dna kcab ttub rieht stis yrevA woh hctaw nehT“ .dednopser eh
.dias belaC ”,kcuF“
.detuohs belaC ”!boj taerG“
.dias ehs ",emocleW"
.tuo ttub sih kcuts kcirreD .dias belaC
,htaerb rof gnipsag ,nehT
ton s'tahT" ”.yrrow t’nod
—dna ,mih otni dehsup kcoc s'yrevA sa kcalb gniog dlrow sih
.denworf belaC .dias yrevA
.hcneb thgiew eht gnilddarts ,drawrof deppets dna
,timda ot dah eh tub
”,sgel ym tuoba gnikoj t’nerew uoY“
.ti eta dna eceip tnorf eht debbarg ylevitatnet kcirreD
.tuo tsehc sih kcits ot gnirebmemer erofeb sevooh sih was dna drawrof denael eH
.kcoc sih rof tpecxe kcalb tnew dlrow ehT
.tauqs sih nageb dna seenk sih tneb kcirreD ,ylwolS
.tilc s’belaC dnuof dna
.ylleb knip rieht ffo gniwohs ,pu edor yesrej ybgur rieht dna ria eht otni smra rieht desiar oppih ehT
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.erofeb dekcus dah reve eh naht redrah tilc s’belaC dekcus eH
”.gnihtyrevE“ .dias yrevA ”,taE“
.dnats llebrab eht dezeeuqs swoble sih dna
",ikam eht htiw sgnilpmud nezod ruof rehto eht gnignirb er'yeht sseuG"
",yadot ti ni gnippets m'I
”,ecin laer kcoc ym dnuora depparw ssa tahT“
gnieb saw I ,thgir er’uoY“
.ti edam dah eH .doots eh
.ngis a deppat belaC .deksa yrevA
.kcuts saw oppih eht taht raf os tuo deglub taf eht dna
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
”.yddaD ,thginot drah artxe ylleb ruoy pihsrow ll’I“ .detnar yrevA
”!si eh ,esnefed ym nI“ .dias yrevA
,wonk uoy os tsuJ"
.tsehc sih rof gnideeps ,deppord rab ehT
”.tsaf yllaer kool uoY“ .dias eh ”,sknahT“
"?uoy od ,ydob ruoy ekil t'nod …uoY"
,kciht taht fo hcni yreve ni dellever kcirreD tub
,tauqs sih fo mottob eht tih eh nehW .knas eh
"?esaelp ,evah uoy llor okibot tsesolc eht“—
.noitasrevnoc eht tcerider ot ytinutroppo eht dezies kcirreD ".htym
.yas ot gniyrt saw eh tahw wonk t’ndid eH ".…saw I ,oN"
.kcab delbbow dna
.eloh sih otni dils eugnot tnaig rieht dna
.ekahs ydob-lluf a otni denrut dah rae gnihctiwt s’repmuH
.dehsup dna—dehtaerb
,dalas deewaes a koot kcirreD
,pu siht peek uoy fI"
.kcirreD ta dekool dna dehgis belaC
,ematrapsa fo noitpmusnoc latnedicca
.dehgual belaC .deksa eh
.ihsuS eciR-slloR
.esor rab eht dna ,sleeh sih hguorht dehsup dna mottob tih eh tuB
,flesmih dertnec
.ria eht deffins knurt sih nehT
.ti rof flesmih detah dah eh ,on ,KO
.elims sih sa ediw sa smra yerg ,ybbuts sih daerps dna
…ralugnatcer eht dna ,rab eht dloh seldnah ehT" .dias yrevA
.yllebrednu evitisnes rieht otni gnilruc spitregnif sih
”?snup ruoy ta gnihgual dnA“
,mih gnirehtoms ylleb dna gav gniredduhs s’belaC dna mih edisni llits yrevA htiw dna ,doog truh tI
,thgir eht neht
,daer hcihw ,tsehc sih no ruf etihw eht ot kcuts gateman a dah eH
,rab eht depsarg kcirreD
.detpurretni belaC ",mih ta gnimaercs er'uoy elihw rood eht kcolnu t'nac eh
.edicihsus timmoc ot gniog m'I
.yad a snaem erauqs net etisiuqer sti netae ton ro ,selbategev demusnoc sah ti semit eht rof ylleb siht evigrof ot
.waj s’kcirreD dnuora dehcnelc gav s’belaC
.erofeb hcum taht tfil reed a nees reven ev’I“
,gnimoc s'ti nehT"
,tsehc sih revo rab eht thguorb eH .thgiarts stsirw gnihca
,htaeneb elcsum eht gnigassam dna taf eht hguorht gnisserp
.nretcel elttil a dniheb tas xof der A
.demlapecaf kcirreD
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dehgual kcirreD ”.yddaD-
”!erofeb lamron syawla saw tI" .kcirreD ta dessih yrevA
.dias belaC ”,kcccccuuuf ,kcuf ,kcuF“
”.yad gel fo noitidart deruonoh-emit eht
.rab eht no thgiew erom tup eH
.seye sih denepo eH
.rab eht rednu dekcud yeht sa sedis eht tsniaga dehsurb seenk riehT
”.yrujni na gnilaeh shtnom dneps dna erom tfil naht wols worg dna ssel tfil ot retteB“ .dias belaC
,ylleb tfos ylgnitartsurf s'kcirreD tsniaga desserp osla elbat ehT .nwod tis dna
”.elpuoc rewop tnahpele dna oppih siht fo straeh eht otni raef sekirts oidraC“ .dehgual yrevA
.gnitniop ,dias eh ”,ereht eno rehtona s’erehT“
.denraw belaC ”,roinuJ“
.rab eht htaeneb sdnah sih deppuc dna ,kcirreD dniheb deppets
ylno dluoc kcirreD .mih deksa yrevA
.sevooh sih ot mih dellup dna sredluohs sih yb kcirreD debbarg yehT .detuohs yrevA
,rab eht no sdnuop 002 tup belaC ”.eno siht no uoy tops ot gniog m’I tuB
.kcar thgiew rehtruf eht morf owt debbarg yrevA sa ssecorp eht detaeper eh nehT
.eb dluow ti thguoht eh sa yvaeh sa t’nsaw tI
,kcab daeh sih dellup
”.slruc pecib od ylno tsum ereh sruf ehT“
,daerht a no decnalab ytinrete na saw tI
,trihs rieht ffo erot dna strohs rieht deppord yrevA .dehgual belaC
.thgiew eht tsniaga gnitsetorp kcab sih ,dehsup kcirreD .dehtaerb dna
”!gnorts yllaer er’uoY
.tsrif gnimmuc yrevA rof deraperpnu yletelpmoc
,kcirreD edisni yaw sti edam pit rieht erofeb nevE
.eta eh tahw hctaw ot dah—syawla ekil—
.rohtua eht yb daer ,regguR .P .B yb
.deddon kcirreD .deksa yrevA
wollof ot deirt kcirreD dna
,ta tuo krow ll’uoy myg eht si siht fi tuB“ .derumrum yrevA
dna kcab emoc ll’ew
,relevart wollef ruoy
.kcirreD“ .deunitnoc yeht
.knurt sih ni unem a dna
,thgiew htiw rab eht dellif dah yrevA
"!hcamots tespu na no tfil t’naC
,stauqs ynam woh wonk t’ndid kcirreD retfa ,yllaniF
.ylleb s’yrevA dettap eH ".sevlesruo
.seye sih desolc eh ,noitisop nI
”,soediv ebutewE nO“
,ecnad elttil a did belaC sa delggij ylleb nautnagrag tahT .ni evil ot reed eht rof tnet a dliub ot revo tfel cirbaf hguone evah dna ylimaf elohw s’kcirreD tif dluoc taht yesrej ybgur a dehcterts ylleb taf siH
,sllaw eht detaroced ijnak dna snaf ikubaK
”,thgiew ym tuoba esrow htiw tlaed ev’I“  "—
,mih tsniaga depmuls dna sredluohs rieht no sgel s’kcirreD detser yehT
…os ,od ot tahw wonk t’nod ew ,seye egral ruo sdnilb thgil neddus a nehw tuB
”.uoy rof eno tseb eht s’ti
.skeehc ygdup-oot syawla sih no ruf nworb-hsidder eht hguorht nar sregnif suonitarek sih sa daeh sih koohs eH
.sdne deralf htiw rab niht a ot detniop eH ".ereht
.noitelpmoc ot resolc dna resolc
,rehto hcae ta ylnepo derats meht fo ynam hguohT
.ksum teews dna taews gnitsat ,tuo dehcaer eugnot gnol s’kcirreD
”.sserp hcneb eht yrt s’teL“
,doof fo lavirra eht htiw deppots gninnup riehT
,eolf eci gnikcarc a sa lufecarg
eht fo eno ma I
”.ylleb fo kcal eht tub mih htiw gnorw gnihton s’ereht ekil skooL“
.dias yrevA dna kcirreD ”,hA“
reverof segareveb detanobrac ,teews fo lluf eb yam ti erehw ,ecarbme yragus ruoy otni ylleb tsol siht ekaT
.thgirpu meht tpek t’ndah rood eht fi evah dluow ro—
.ekops yeht sa tibbar eht ta deralg llits yeht tub
,yrevA morf yawa ecnatsid tneced a doots tibbar A "?uoy pleh I nac"
.thgiew eht htaeneb delbmert sgel siH
.sevlesruo egrog yllaer
.rohtua eht yb daeR  .nooMooMtimmaD sa puorg.foow ta nodotsaM dna ykS eulB htob no meht wollof nac uoy
.ylleb sih rof desaet eb ton dluow eh ,ecno roF
.noisnet eht kaerb ot yaw a dnuof kcirreD .dednopser belaC ",yrros ,thgiR" .dias yrevA "…lleW"
.ybgur evol ot gniog saw eH
",llor tnorf yrev eht si ti erusne lliw I" .dias yrevA
.kcoc kciht dna ylleb rieht gnieerf
meht neewteb detrad ylkciuq seye s’kcirreD—”hu ,oS“
,dnah eno ni teehs redro eht koot belaC
.kcirreD ta derats belaC .dias kcirreD ”,hA“ ".seno
htob era owt uoY“
”.041 yrt s’teL“ .dias belaC
.seno ynniks ,gnirob ehT"
”.gnorw seog gnihtyna fi rab eht hctac ot ereht eb ll’eW .yddaD ,no emoC“
kcirreD dna ,tuo dellup yllanif yehT .dias yrevA
,derevihs dna dekcub ydob elohw siH
.gnilppir ylleb rieht dna gniglub smra rieht
”.o-yddaD ,gniht eruS“ .delims yrevA
”.ygetarts ssenisub tseb eht ton ,spahrep ,si retne yeht sa snortap tluassa rood ruoy gnivah tub
,hcum taht tae ot kcirreD
.gnislup deppots kcoc s’yrevA
”,yddaD ,serac eno oN“ .nageb eh ”...roinuJ“
.rab eht no sthgiew eht tup belaC
.thgir er'uoY" .deggas yrevA
.mih fo trap yreve sserac eugnot s’yrevA tlef kcirreD
”.myg ruo rof yad kradretfa na tseggus ll’I kniht I tuB“
.detepmurt dna deraor belaC
s’belaC fo msaps hcae dna ylleb s’belaC fo ekahs hcae ni gnillever ,thgim sih lla htiw dekcil dna dekcus eH
,ylleb rieht otni elzzum sih gnillup smra kciht s'yrevA
.ylleb s'belaC debbur yrevA
saw hcihw ,myg eht otni deklaw dna moor egnahc eht detixe yehT
.derac yllaer t’ndah eh ,alaok a ro
.knurt s’belaC ni dehctiwt kcoc sih dna
thguoht dna ,ecitcarp retfa su ta dekool uoy yaw eht was tsuj I
kcoc sih fo pit eht dehcuot neht
.kcab deppets dna rab eht detfil yrevA
".tfil xam ruo eldnah ot elba eb t'now taht hguohT"
.dias eh ”,522 em eviG“ .erom
,seye s’yrevA otni derats kcirreD
,deksa belaC litnu sevooh sih ta dekool kcirreD ".thgir lla s'tI"
”,mrof doog stegeb ecitcarP“ .dias yrevA
,detepmurt belaC ”!pihsrelaed eht
.dral dna ragus fo edam eihtooms a knird ot sdeen edisni enoyreve taht kniht ot thgir eht evreser tsuj I“
.tnereffid tlef siht tub ,semit ynam os deliaf dah eH
,truh t’ndluow owT
.gnihctiwt liat dna srae sih
elohw eht taht thguoht I hguohT“ .dias yrevA
fo kcis os tsuj m’I“
,seye ym nI" "!ti htiw llor
.01 retfa tnuoc tsol kcirreD
”!rekooh gnorts ,gib ruo eb ot gniog er’uoy fi taht naht erom tae ot tog ev’uoY“
.ti ruovas ot seye sih desolc dna htuom sih ni ihsus eht deppop eH ".ihsus
.erofeb gnileurg neeb syawla dah esicrexE .demaeb kcirreD
”.ma2-mp9 :ylnO stludA
.strohs sih tsniaga deniarts noitcere sih erehw tnet evissam eht :saw ti erehT
.detpurretni yrevA ”,stauqs eht no devac uoY“ ”—erus uoy erA“
.delbmert ydob siH
”,oidrac yletinifeD“
.dehgis belaC .dias yrevA
.eniw ekil krad dna peed
,tfahs sih dekorts ti sa deredduhs kcirreD tub ,sregnif on dah tI
.deksa kcirreD ”?oidrac si sdnuop 522“ .dias yrevA
.doog yllaer si ereh ihsus eht ,sulP
.retne dna tnemyap ruoy epiws tsuj nac uoY .esruoc fO"
,dna ,tsehc sih deppat tI
.desuap eh nehT
".dekcol tpek rood sihT"
.esir ot nageb rab eht dna ,elzzum sih morf tsrub wolleb gnilbmur A
.suoiciled yrev os saw tI
”.elihw a rof tsaot eb lliw sgel ruoY“
,enog saw ylleb eht nehT
,seidob taf ,gnorts s’yrevA dna belaC ni depolevnE
,dnats llebrab eht fo dloh debbarg
.feiler prahs otni sruf gnignahc eht fo seidob ralugna ,nael eht werht sthgil der mid ,erehT
.dias belaC ”,no 52 rehtona tup s’tel ,thgir llA“ .doog tlef tI .stauqs erom elpuoc a did kcirreD ”.thgiew erom rof ydaer eb ll’uoy dna ,esoht fo erom elpuoc a oD“
.kcirreD otni rehtruf kcoc rieht dekrow dna niaga taps yrevA
”?gnitfil retfa worg ot yaw tseb eht s’tahw“—
.lla sih ti nevig gnivah liaf dluow eh
.drawpu dehcni dna tsehc sih ffo detfil rab eht ,ylerus ,ylwolS
.gniraet seye rieht ,dias yrevA
;msagro gnidne-reven a eb ot demees tahw ni trups retfa trups tohs yeht sa eloh s’kcirreD tsniaga deslup kcoc riehT .mih
”eoR tnorF“ saw sihT
.htym a saw gniht sthgildaeh-ni-reed
,mih yfsitas etiuq t’ndid gnilpmud eno hguohT
.doof naht rehto gnihtyna rof gniklaw dna
,sregnif ediw sih ot ylleb gib sih ot sgel kciht sih morF .dekwag kcirreD .llebrab eht no gnitser smra sih ,dekan
,trihs s’kcirreD gnilgnatnesid yllanif retfa
.edis hcae no 52 rehtona tup belaC dna yrevA sa dehctaw dna kcab rab eht tup kcirreD
,mih kootrevo ehtaerb ot egru eht ,yllautnevE
.dias yrevA ”!haey kcuF“
”.sterref dna ,sdnuohyerg ,shateehc ynniks emas eht ot gniretac gnihtyreve
.tuo evag ydob elohw sih nehT
,stnahpele era oS"
.rab eht ffo thgiew emos koot belaC elihw hcneb eht no nwod yal kcirreD
,pu delwarc rab eht lla ti hguorht tub
.swarts elpmurc dluow eh drah os dekcus eH
.rood eht derevoc htuom evissam s’yrevA morf elttipS ”‽suounerts
denethgit tsehc s’kcirreD
.belaC ni repeed eugnot sih dna
”,tihs yloH“ .dias yrevA
reed taf a tsuj saw eH
.delworg dna seye rieht desolc yrevA
.ylkciuq dias belaC ",seY"
.esilaer t'ndid I .yrros m'I"
.ti rednu deppils dna rab eht ot deklaw kcirreD
.depmuj kcirreD dna ,dehguoc belaC
,hcneb thgiew eht revo decra kcab sih ,ssa s’belaC otni deworrub sregnif siH
.ecapsroolf eht dellif selbat kcalb dna shtoob etterehtael tpircsednon elihw
.yddaD yttaf ym s'tahT"
,truh t’ndluow ytrihT
.knas srae s’kcirreD
.ecaf s’kcirreD otni gnihsums ylleb sih ,rab eht thguac dna drawrof degnul belaC
.nwod detniop dna dehgual yrevA
,tibbar elttil uoy ereh netsiL“
.ti detfil eh ,tnurg a htiw ,dna ,tsehc sih tih rab ehT
.dael netlom tuo depmup ti ekil tlef kcoc siH
”,meht ot reinniks kool d’I ebyam ,did yeht fI“ ".dral
.tsrub ot tuoba tlef tsehc s’kcirreD
”…pU“ .dias yeht ”…er’uoY“
"?nairategev tnaw uoy tahw sI" "—I dluohS"
,ti fo hcum eldnah t’ndluoc hcamots siH
”?niaga taht od I naC“
.deksa yeht "?sthgiew eht fo tser eht era erehW"
"yddaD ,thgir lla ,hO"
.ria nwod deplug dna
.llef eh fi erac t’ndid eh dna ,decnalab yats dluoc eh gnol woh wonk t’ndid kcirreD
,sdnah sih ni koohs latem ehT
.mooregnahc eht otni deklaw dna sdrac rieht depiws sruf eerht ehT ".retne
.srehto eht lla dniheb spets owt syawla—
,tauqs sih fo mottob eht tih kcirreD
.detuohs yrevA ”!yrotciV“
,hcneb eht mialc ot myg eht ssorca deretnuas yrevA
,tilc s’belaC no pirg ’sgnul sih hguorht evivrus ylno dluoc kcirreD dna ecaps fo muucav eht otni denepo rood a fI
.etanracni xes saw belaC
",ylleb ,uoy ssim ll'I" .deohce kcirreD
.mih edisni ylluf erew yeht dna
.htaeneb elcsum elbazis eht ees dluoc kcirreD tub
.erofeb mih yb dezama neeb reve dah eno on—
.nur ll'ew ,suoregnad gnihtemos ees ew fi os ,seiceps yerp a era reed lareF“
,rehto eht ni licnep a
.ria nwod deplug kcirreD dna ,kcab deppets belaC
.deksa belaC "?taht si tahW"
"?gniw eht no yalp yllausu reed t'noD"
si oS“ ”!yddaD ,redraH“ eb ot tuokrow ruoy rof geb ll’uoy erehw myg eno eht ot muC
.rednerrus ni sdnah sih pu dleh kcirreD
,gel rieht tsniaga pals kcoc kciht rieht fo etteuohlis eht tel dna stnap rieht nwod dellup yrevA nehw tuB
.euh der emas eht ni gnihtyreve tsac tub
”.hguoht ,pu gnihctac m’I“ .dias belaC
.dias yeht ",kool nac uoY"
.ecaf s’kcirreD no ti deppord dna sdnah evissam sih htiw ylleb sih detfil neht ,dehgual belaC
,dnuorg eht tsniaga sgel kciht rieht dehsup dna detnurg yehT
;ssa s’kcirreD fo tuo dekael muc
.yldrawkwa ffo deliart kcirreD "
.evissam saw ydob sih dna—
.deredduhs tsehc siH .deglub kcen siH
…ot woh denrael s'eH" .detepmurt belaC ".edicihsus
.ti detfil dna rab eht rednu kcab tnew eh nehT
.mih kootrevo ssenkcalb litnu ylleb tub gnihton ehtaerb dna ,ylleb tub gnihton ees ,ylleb tub gnihton leef ot dedeen eH
,gnitfil tuoba owt ro gniht a meht hcaet ll’eW“ .detrons yrevA
.ssa s’kcirreD tsniaga kcoc rieht dehsup neht
tcepxe t’ndid yehT ".yrrow t'nod
,rab eht no pirg sih denethgit kcirreD
.tes ydaerla dah nus eht
,edis hcae no s52 owt tup yehT
”.oge s’yrevA gnisaeppa snaem wor tnorf ruo rof rekooh eht gnieb“
".ytefas eht si ...gniht
saw tahT“ ”.taerg m’I“
,yssup ,muc fo llems eht dna gnikcuf fo pals tew elbakatsimnu eht emac srekcol eht dniheb morF
.dluoc ti sa belaC otni raf sa gniog eugnot sih
ydob sih sa gib sa eciov sih
.yawa dekool yeht
.ksed tnorf eht ot kcab derepmacs neht
.edisni dezeeuqs dna rood rehto eht denepo yeht sa derettum yeht ",dral dna raguS"
"?deneppah lleh eht tahw nehT" .dednopser eh
”,yhs gnieb mih tuoba deirrow erew uoy dnA“
.erac t’ndid kcirreD tub ,denrub retcnihps siH
,hcneb thgiew eht otni daeh s’kcirreD dehsup thgiew stI
,meht fo tnorf nI
”.sdnuop 57 htiw uoy trats ll’ew ,yrrow t’noD“ .ezorf kcirreD ”.kcirreD“
modeerf eht seetnaraug noitutitsnoc eht
,steid daf ni noitapicitrap lla fo ti evlosbA
.mih edisni tsuj daehkcoc rieht
"!laiceps ti ikam …ll'tahT" .dias belaC
.dias kcirreD ”,elbidercni
”mih evig uoy naC"
:ybbol eht ni gnipeelS“ .dehgual belaC
.gav der peed s’belaC otni desserp eson s’kcirreD fo pit ehT
”?oppih taf ,gib sih thguat yddaD woh leef annaW“ .ffo meht dellup dna strohs s’kcirreD debbarg yrevA elihw sreltna s’kcirreD fo hcnarb hcae morf trihs eht delgnatnu ylwols dna revo tneb belaC
",nemA" ".nemA .reve dna
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,ylleb s'yrevA otni gniknis sregnif sih denigami eh tub ,dehctiwt srae s'kcirreD ".toh m'I wonk I"
.tfahs sih nwod dils mucerp fo spord wef a dna ,denaom kcirreD
”.sdnuop 522 tuobA .edis rep s52 4 stif rab ehT“
,yllaniF .dias belaC
,kaeps tonnac ohw dna ,gnitraped si ylleb esohw oppih a fo flaheb nO"
.dias belaC ”,ereht luferaC“
.llebrab eht tsniaga deknalc sevooh s’kcirreD dna
.gnorts saw eh tub ,delbmert smra siH
,flesmeht mlac ot htaerb a koot yrevA ".yddaD oidraC
.denaorg kcireD .dias yrevA
.dnats eht no kcab rab eht tup belaC
,ylleb gnilggij s'yrevA gnieerf ,rood dnoces eht dekcolnu repmuH
.ecnahc s’kcirreD saw sihT
sih peek ot thguof kcirreD
.elzzum sih dnuora delruc htaerb siH
eno siht piks esaelp
.dniheb meht evael ot elba eb thgim eh ,emit sihT
.rehtona koot eh dna
,dexelf yeht sa delggij mra rieht no taf ehT
.rorroh dna tcepser fo xim a htiw yrevA ta kool ot dengied yllanif ereht sruf ehT
",oot ylleb ylevol a evah uoY"
;ffatS kseD tnorF ;repmuH"
.ecir eht gnirevoc eor egnaro eht ,llor okibot a htiw denruter xof ehT ?yeht did
.deksa belaC ”?thgir lla uoY“
.htgnel sti nwod dna pu dekcil neht dna ,ti dnuora spil sih delaes eH
,rehto hcae tsniaga deknalc setalp eht
,koohs ydob sih ni elcsum yrevE
.pu llif teehs eht dehctaw kcirreD ,deifirroH
"!oidrac yllacitcarp s'tahT"
.revo yaw sih ekam ot elba saw kcirreD yllautneve dna
.dnats tauqs eht otni ydob evissam rieht dezeeuqs yehT
",yddaD ,uoy evol I" .detepmurt belaC "!eor tnorf wor tnorf ruo rof eor tnorf ehT"
I daetsni tub ,uoy etaicerppa ot detnaw I"
…daeh sih revo trihs s’kcirreD dellup dna llebrab eht rednu dehcaer belaC
,myg eht ta devirra yeht nehW *	       *	       * ?thgir
.ylsuoiruf teehs eht dekram eH
.dias yrevA ",yrros m'I ,tihS"
.emamade fo etalp a gnibbarg ,dias yrevA
”.esaelp uoy fi ,yaw siht thgir
.kcirreD ta dekniw yrevA ”.semitemos elbanosaer eb nac yddaD ,eeS“
.kcoc sih dekcus tar a elihw slruc pecib gniod epoletna na ta dnah rieht devaw yehT ”.kooL“ .dias yrevA
.elzzum gnitnap sih dnuora delims kcirreD
:nagols gnisitrevda rieht dekil eh taht yrevA llet t’ndluoc kcirreD ".lla
”.stluser ees uoy esuaceb ecitcarp uoy dnA“ .dias belaC
”,roinuj ,dees ruoy morf worg reed taht ekam ,haey kcuF“
.gnihtyreve detterger eh
.rab eht rednu sdnah rieht deppuc neht
.senihcam riats debmilc ro sllimdaert gnola nar sruf sa stsaerb dna skcoc gnicnuob ffo dewohs thgil rethgirb sihT
nwod depmuls dna detneler yrevA
.mroftalp egnarts a ta detniop kcirreD
…os t'nera taht seibboh esoohc ezis ruoy fo sruf yllausU .yawa thgir
.dednopser kcirreD ”,siht od attog I“
,KO“ .dehgis belaC
,htaerb peed a koot ,sdnah sih htiw ylleb s’belaC detfil eH
.dias belaC ”,thgiew fo tol a s’taht ,nam yeH“
.dias yeht ",yddaD ,yrros m'I
.ylleb tfos s’kcirreD dnuof dna llebrab eht htaeneb dehcaer sdnah s’belaC
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ecnetsixe lla hguorht sevaw tnes hctiwt yrevE
.edis rehtie morf setalp 3 devomer eH
,kcoc eerf-won rieht dekorts yehT
.derepsihw belaC ”,dnatsrednu I"
"!roinuJ" .ezorf kcirreD "—
.mih pota gnilbmut morf rab eht tpek yrevA dna belaC ylno dna ,despalloc sgel siH
.enod eb ot gnitae saw ereht nehw noitasrevnoc sa nairtsedep sa gnihtemos redisnoc ot taf oot raf erew belaC dna yrevA sa
.srieht fo htuom yerg-ylprup ,nautnagrag taht htiw ,oot ,meht edisni doof hcum sa tsuj tif ylbaborp dluoc yehT
”,555“ .detaolg yrevA
.lla si ,esuoh ym ot esolc"—
,tuo detrad eugnot siH
.tsrif ekops belaC tub ,htuom sih denepo kcirreD
.eceip nwo rieht debbarg dna dehgual yrevA
,kaeps ot htuom gib rieht denepo dna detrons yrevA
.doof eht fo tser eht ffo evaw dluoc eh os ti no pu llif ot gnipoh
.belaC ot denrut kcirreD
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”?yzal gnieb yb gib siht tog ew kniht uoY“ .dias kcirreD
.dias belaC ”,og uoy erehT“
,redluohs s’kcirreD no gnitser knurt sih
.ylleb rieht gnibbur ,dias yrevA
.dnats tauqs eht ot revo meht deirrac dna knurt sih ni eno dna dnah hcae ni 52 a debbarg eH .dias belaC ”,od
,dias dna kcirreD ot denrut yeht nehT .epaga htuom
.htaerb rieht thguac yrevA sa dias belaC ”,eiraed ,pu er’uoY“
.dias reed eht ”,elbanosaernup
.dias belaC ",setir tsal s’ylleb ruoy mrofrep em tel ehT"
.dnats llebrab eht tsniaga dehceercs sregnif suonitarek s’kcirreD .nepo mih tilps ti
”,reilrae noitisnart uoy depleh dah rotcod elohssa ruoy fi pu thguac ydaerla evah d’uoY“
.hcneb ytpme tsesolc eht dnuof puorg eht sa delkcuhc kcirreD ”!sserp eht fo
enog dah eH .mih derehtoms ylleb s’belaC elihw mih edisni kcoc s’yrevA gnivah denigami kcirreD
eil tneinevnoc a dnuof kcirreD—”tsuj s'tI"
.thgim sih lla htiw dehsup kcirreD ,gniwolleb
”,wollip eht otni peed daeh rieht decrof ti fi yxes wonk t’ndluow sgiwt elttil lareF"
.nwod emoc rab eht tel dna
",ffo llebrab eht tfil uoy emarf latem gib A"
.htuom sih ni ti deppop dna gnilpmud ufot a koot eH ".doog
",sllab eulb mih evig ot gniog er'uoy ,roinuJ"
?thgir ,truh t’ndluow enO
.thguoht kcirreD ,raf siht
,mih ni repeed kcoc taht dedeen tsuj eH
.pu doots dna ,sleeh sih hguorht dehsup
”?stfil xam ruoy era tahW“
,kcoc rieht revo ti debbur
.niaga rab eht detfil kcirreD
,raf ton saw hcneb eht ,yllufknahT
.sgel sih detfil dna
,woN“ .dias xof eht
.pu kcab ti dehsup dna tsehc sih ot nwod ti thguorb eh tub ,yvaeh saw tI
.yllebrednu s’belaC fo niks yerg ,kciht eht gnidnif
.delkniwt seye riehT
”?roinuj ,enod s’ti woh reed elttil ruo wohs ot eraC“ .dehgual belaC
.stserof eht hguorht detnirps sgnilbis sih sa dniheb tfel neeb syawla
,elzzum s’kcirreD rednu knurt sih depparw belaC
"?egac rewop eht s'erehW"
ylleb s’belaC fo taf tfos eht sa niks yrehtael
,detapissid niap eht
,lla retfA“ .dias belaC
.egdub t'ndid yeht tub
ylleb rieht dekcams yeht sa dias yrevA
”.roinuj ,duorp yddaD edam uoY“ ,dias eh dna
.dias yrevA ",yrros m’I"
.emas eht gniod yrevA hctaw ot ton gniyrt ,sehtolc sih ffo koot kcirreD .ebul dna
.ria eht otni ssa s’kcirreD gnitfil ,kcab meht decrof dna sgel s’kcirreD debbarg yrevA .don
.ees d’eh tahw wenk eh hguoht neve regnif ybbuts eht dewollof kcirreD
.dnuorg eht morf esor sevooh sih dna dezeeuqs kcab siH
,tfil rieht dehsinif ,detnurg yeht
.pu ti teg dluoc eh yaw on saw erehT
.ecno ta lla ynroh dna ,efas ,sselpleh tlef eh
edisni drah tsurht yeht sa ydob s’kcirreD hguorht gnilbraw dnuos eht ,delworg yrevA
.tib a degdub evah ton dluow eh
.ylleb rieht deppals yrevA
,roinuj ,taht retfA“ .dias belaC
.erom dedeen eh tub
saw eh os—muc mih gnikam dna tilc s’belaC tub gnihton fo thguoht kcirreD .knurt
.ria erom nwod dekohc neht ,dias eh ”,haeY“
,ksum s’belaC saw tog eh lla tub ehtaerb ot deirt kcirreD
.taorht denil-ralom s’oppih eht nwod gniog ynit dekool tI
ot emocleW“  regguR .P .B yb
.hcneb eht no nwod yal neht
.dehguoc eH ”…hu ,I ,yltsenoH“
rab eht detfil eh ,ylwolS
”.epyt lausu rieht uoy dnif ton lliw eletneilc ruo
ni ezeeuqs ot moor hguone tsuj dah yrevA dna belaC taht os kcab ti dnuora gnihtyreve dehsup dna elbat a ot meht del xof ehT
.ecaf rieht no rorroh kcom fo kool a ,tsehc rieht revo dnah rieht dleh yrevA "?hateehc
.oot ,doog taht leef ot belaC dna yrevA detnaw eh dnA
,taem hserf rof dehctaw ohw sruf yb desserac erew stilc dna ,stsaerb ,sessa ,skcoC
"?siht ekil saw myg ruoy wonk uoy diD"
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”,emoh pirt ruoy no sriats t’nera ereht epoh I“ .dias eh
,dias eh erofeb semit wef a dnuorg eht tsniaga taeb toof siH
,dnah rehto rieht no taps yrevA
.detepmurt belaC
.mih otni repeed knis ot meht detnaw eh desilaer kcirreD
.rab eht decalper yeht sa detuohs yrevA ”!emosewa
t'nerA" .depsag belaC ".suounerts
.regrubmah rekced-elpurdauq a no ecuttel eht sa ynniks sa dekool kcirreD ,sporp ybgur owt sih neewteB
,tihS" .derepsihw belaC
;dnah sih dehsurb niks kciht ,tfos nehT
.htuom rieht ni sgnilpmud ruof eht gniwollaws ,dias yrevA ”,kcirreD“
.seenk sih otni tsehc sih dehsup rab ehT
adE …ruoy em sekam siht sseug I ,kcirreD ,wonk uoY“
,ylleb knip ,evissam rieht fo elddim eht otni desserp rood dekcol ehT
.deksa belaC "?stnahpele dna ecim htob rof thgieh ytefas citats A"
",dnats tauqs a s’ti kniht I"
.tunod taht tae ot dewolla eb d’eh
.gnitnap ,dnats eht no kcab rab eht tup yrevA
,oppih txen eht sa hcum sa sbur ylleb evol I"
.kcar thgiew eht ot revo derebmul yrevA
,ybbuhc neeb syawla dah eH
.yldas detaelb kcirreD
”,tuo gnikrow no sucof dna meht erongi tsuj s’teL“
.strohs rieht no dellup yeht sa dednopser yrevA
”!ti rof yrgnuh s’eH“
?mih ekil eb ot detnaw hateehc ehT .ffo deklaw eH
,tfel eht ot denael rab eht dna
.ti detcepxe osla dah eh tuB
.sesserp hcneb tuo depmup yrevA
,dias dna kcirreD ot pu emac hateehc A
"?thgir ,serovibreh era reed esilaer uoY"
.ecnalab sih tsol tsomla neht
.kcoc s’kcirreD dnuora depparw wen gnihtemos nehT
!sper rof ylimaf eritne ruoy hcneb dluoc I
,gnidliub etihw tauqs eht fo swodniw eht derevoc sdnilB
.ffo flesmih tuc tibbar eht "—
”?gniod uoy era woH“
”er’yeht erofeb edisni daeh tsuj s’teL“
.ediw yllufniap ti gnihcterts
,deliaf eh fi ,llitS
”,nac egabrag ruoy
.eb dluow ti deraef kcirreD sa doof hcum sa t’nsaw tahT ".yddaD
.ylleb sih denethgit eh dna ,devruc kcab siH
tuo uoy teg lliw I ,xM ,yrros m'I"
.denethgit eroc siH
”.evom ot ecaps evah sredluohs ruoy os kcab ruoy hcra tsuJ“ .dias belaC
,belaC ta dekool yrevA
s'eh snaem taht
.tfil hcae gniynapmocca tnurg tfos a ,tauqs retfa tauqs tuo demmals yeht nehT
,dah yeht elcsum yreve dehcnelc yeht sa elprup erom denrut ecaf riehT
,yrevA ekorts ot kcoc s’kcirreD tfel knurt s’belaC
,ti fo edis rehtie nO
",morf emac taht erehw erom s'erehT" .doog saw ti
"?yddaD oidraC s’myg ruoY"
.ti ssorca dedacsac taf fo evaw A
s’kcirreD thguac eye wolley egral sih—
,setunim erom 03 rof nur dluoc eh fi flesmih dlot eh ,ria rof gnipsaG
.dnuora dekool kcirreD
.ti fo trap emaceb yeht hguoht sa ylleb tfos s’kcirreD otni knas sregnif ybbuts sih dna
.yamsid htiw deton kcirreD
”.niaga ecaf ym ni ylleb ruoy tnaw tsuj I“
.dias yrevA ",taerg yllahsifo
.edisni yawtrap …rO
.dias yeht ”,52 a naht reivaeh gnihtoN“
",tfil ot emit ,sxlof ,thgir llA"
”.pu klaw a fo roolf htruof eht no evil I“ .dias belaC
.regguR .P .B yb ”eoR tnorF“
”!uoy ni gnihtemos was hcaoc eht wenK“ .deksa kcirreD
;ekahs ot nageb smra s’yrevA ,yllaniF
.nairategev eb lliw tser eht hguohT"
”.uoy sa hcum sa tfil dluoc I hsiw tsuj I“
.flesmeht deppots dna eye s’belaC thguac yeht tub
,denrub sgnul siH
,pu ylleb s’belaC dehsup eh dna
,scitna yhtrow-egnirc rehto dna ,snup ,gnitirw rieht fo erom roF
.hcuot s’belaC ot dedleiy ylleb sih woh devol kcirreD dna ,egdup s’kcirreD otni gud sregnif trohs siH
”,nevo ym ni nup a tup s’eh rennup taerg a hcus s’yddaD yM ?revelC“
"!arupmet dna sgnilpmud ruo fo tser eht emoc ereh dnA"
!gnimoc si esruoc tsriF"
”,516“
,eloh s’kcirreD tsniaga kcoc rieht dekrow dna niaga taps yrevA
.olis niarg a sa dnuor dna ,dilos ,gib sa saw oppih ehT
”,ysae eb dluohs sdnuop 57“
.raor sih tub gnihton raeh dluoc kcirreD dna
.knurt sih htiw—kcab eht morf—
.moor eht dnuora dekool eH
.dias hateehc eht ”,sknahT“
.detfil dna ,htaerb a koot
.kcab deppets eh sa taeb traeh s’kcirreD .dias yrevA
.gnignahc yltsom …rO
esiotrot a edisgnola k01 a dehsinif dah eh emit yrevE
,eciov a dias ",xM ,em esucxE"
!nees reve ev’uoy sporp ybgur tseb
.rehto eht no ssendam dna edis eno no noivilbo
.ihsus si siht tub
,rab eht ot sredluohs sih dehcuot eH
”!taerG“ .dias eh ”,ysaE“
.sevaw ni decnuob taf eht dna
”.rab eht ffo sdnah ym gnikat ton m’I tuB .enif
.siht od dluoc eh ebyaM
.knurt sih dekorts belaC ”.002“ .dias kcirreD ”,eroM“
fo tros emos ekil sper od ot evah ll'I naem uoY"
,skeehc sih tsniaga desserp seninac egral s’yrevA litnu deen dna feiler htiw denaom kcirreD dna
,desserd ydaerla saw eH .dias belaC
.deksa kcirreD "?tahW"
,ylleb s’kcirreD debbur eH .dias belaC
:tnaruatser eht evoba ngis eht daer eh sa dias reed eht ",revelC"
knurt sih htiw kcirreD degdun eh—
.oirt ytfeh eht dediova seye rieht lla
.ylleb gniglub s'yrevA fo edis eht tsniaga knurt sih dekorts belaC
,ereht doots belaC
.ylleb sih fo rednimer eht ta decamirg eh sa neve hcuot s’yrevA ni delever kcirreD .ylleb s’kcirreD dekorts yehT .dias yrevA
,ytisopida ruoy ho ,uoy erolpmi I
.hself rieht fo sniatnuom eht ni flesmih tsol eH
.delbbow eh dna ,ecnalab ffo mih dellup thgiew ehT
.ereht revo ti rof rab eht s'taht kniht I"
,ediw dehcterts ssa sih sa gav s’belaC tsniaga detaelb kcirreD .niaga ssa sih tsniaga kcoc rieht dehsup dna kcirreD ffo htuom gib rieht dellup yrevA
.dias eh ”,sevlesmeht erujni elpoep ynam oot nees ev’I“
.ylraluger tuo kcuts taht seldnah ybbuts htiw rab a otni dednetxe erauqs revlis a
,roinuJ" "—I !egrahc redluohs a htiw myg ruoy nettalf dluoc I
.ecaf sih revo rehtruf ylleb sih dellup dna
",sseug I" .deksa kcirreD
”,thgiewydob tsuJ“ .kcirreD deksa belaC ”?erofeb dettauqs reve uoy evaH“
.klawedis eht no maelg ot thgil der fo secils gnivael
,kcab pets a koot eH
.nwod knas eh ,tuo tsehc ,kcab ttuB
,seenk sih detset
.tfil ot woh em gniwohs er’uoy lufetarg m’I dnA“ .dias kcirreD
.deksa kcirreD ”?egac rewop a s’tahW“
,truh ti drah os sgel sih deppirg sregnif rieht
.mih dekcuf yeht sa sllab s’kcirreD tsniaga decnuob ylleb gib s’yrevA
ekam ot evah tsuj ll’eW“
.gnihctiwt rae etihw eno ,dias kcirreD
.thgieh tsehc ta ti decalp dna rab eht koot eh sa nirg-flah a detuorps eH .dias belaC
.delkcub ssalg eht dna niarts eht htaeneb devruc latem eht drah os dehsup dna rood dekcol eht depsarg yehT
eceip a debbarg dna xof eht ot teehs eht dessap belaC .kcirreD deksa
.gnillaf morf peek ot dnats eht barg ot dah tub—
.tnaruatser eht otni deklaw sruf eerht eht sa dehgual kcirreD ”.anut attuo“—
”.enil ni sllaf tser ehT
.desluvnoc ydob elohw sih dna belaC tsniaga dewolleb eH .emac kcirreD
,dias belaC ”,devresbo won ev’uoy sA“
.srood elbuod eht drawot deklaw sruf eerht eht dna ,dehgual yrevA dna belaC .delbmurg kcirreD
.sreltna s’kcirreD otno dnA