hajilE fo edis rehtie no tuo dehcterts sgel siH
ni yaw on s’erehT
!doog ,doog
.su fo wef a erew erehT“
.uoy rof noitseuq gnikcuf bmud a tog s'enoemos
.retal rof nocixel sih otni evas ot
”,rehtie dehtacsnu evael yltcaxe t’ndid uoy dna ,yad taht ti fo etsat a tog enoyrevE
.strohs sih pu gnillup
.mra eht no pals a mih evag dna pu flesmih dekcip hajilE ,eunitnoc ot eros oot erew tsehc dna staorht rieht nehW
.yawa enohp sih tup eh sa nirg ykcoc a tog hajilE
.tcatnoc eye ekam ot elbanu ,dias eh
?ereh pu eb ot deen enoemos t'nseoD
"?moorhtab eht ni sbojdnah evag uoY"
.eciov sih otni ytirecnis emos gnikrow ,dias eh
”,taht barg emmel ,ereH“
,yawllah eht hguorht depmots eh sa gnimuf yllacitcarp saw eH
,wol tpek eciov sih ,ekops eh nehW
.evlewt ,ekil ,erew eW“ ,deffocs naI
lliw spils gninraw eerhT
,dnuora detrad seye s’naI
,ylevissimsid ria eht ni swap sih dleh hajilE
.elbazingocernu tsomla saw eh ,rufdaeh sih revo ten a htiW
.nooccar eht ta nwod gniralg ,dessih naI ",krej ,ti nac ,ho —ahW" .detnemmoc hajilE
elgnis a esool tel eltsimocac eht edam ti gniraeh tub
,deremmats eh sa trihs sih no snel hcae depiw naI ,elzzum sih ffo meht gnilluP
.si taht ,elpmas eerf a rof...oot
.meht ta detniop dna semag oediv fo wor a ot deppets eH ".htiw
”.swap ruoy fo tuo skoob eht dekconk dooW rehpotsirhC nehw uoy ta dehgual I yrros m’I ,llew ,haeY“
msagro nwo sih ni pu thguac
.trac a fo leehw eht yb revo nur gnieb railimaf oot lla saw eH
.noitcafsitas emos htiw deltsihw hajilE
,eduD“ ,repsihw a ni deunitnoc hajilE
,meht neewteb esuap a saw erehT
,flesmih drah sa tsuj gnihtaerb saw hajilE
.gnivaw regnif a htiw mih ot pu gnimrots emac erah llat ehT
.llaw eht tsniaga gnignah telbat a no gnippat
"!net pot ym ni uoy stup ylisae tahT .renrael tsaF"
a koot dna ,seye sih desolc
,spets sih ni sseniddig a saw erehT
.rehto eht ot yaw eht lla erots eht fo edis eno morf draeh eb ot hguone duol taorht s’naI nwod dekohc plug A ”.derebmemer I ,haeY“
.setaicossa eht naht tsil yrecorg rieht htiw denrecnoc erom ,pihw depirts gnol sih fo deeh elttil koot tramagem eht ni sreppohS
aT a ni nooccar eht ot smra htob dednetxe erah etihw dna kcalb eht ,taht htiW
.dnuorg eht otno tuo erp gnippird kcoc hcni xis sih saw wap nwo sih ni ylthgit depparW
.ylevitcnitsni mra
.htaerb rof detnap eh sa tuo delgnad eugnot sih dna
.enot gnizinortap citsalp a ni dias tnedor eht
.kaep a koot yob rehto eht sa tsuj
.flesmih lortnoc ot deganam tub mra eht no naI pals ot dehcaer hajilE
!WO —b os siht pu kcuf yllaer I diD“
.emit rehtona yrt tsuj dluohs ew ebyaM
dna dnuora dehcraes naI ".syob
.daeh sih koohs tsuj hajilE
.ylsselerac sexob dna sllaw eht ta deppihw liat yleriw siH
.gnihton otni gnirats nepo seye sih htiw taes eht no gnittis llits ,nooccar eht no nwod dekool hajilE
eugnot sih ot sregnif sih thguorb eh ,ylsuoiruC
.rekihhctiH flowereW
,deksa eh sa elzzum sih fo edis hcae gnipsalc swap
.noitarepsaxe detaefed ni tuo tel s’naI elihw ykeehc sdrow s’hajilE
",yrroS" ".krod ,htoomS"
erofeb ffuh erom eno tuo tel hajilE
?deneppah kniht uoy od tahW“
”?enim htiw gnorw s’lleh ehT“
”.emoh kcab emac dna
.redluohs s’rehto eht degdun hajilE
.ecaf sih ni wap a devaw naI nehw pu gnikool ylno
tahT“ .elzzum sih fo ekahs a htiw trohs tuc gnicsinimer sih ,dias naI
.ni kcolc ot sih no dekcilc eh dna
.rethgirb erutuf eht gnikam ydaerla saw edis sih yb naI gnivah tub ,dekcus kroW
.eugnot sih gnikcilc ,deilper eltsimocac eht
.dednuofbmud doots dna sessalg sih htiw delddif nooccar ehT
.moorhtab emas eht gnivael sevlesmeht dnuof yeht retfa ygnilc oot teg yllausu dluow naeS
.tnasaelp eb ot gniog t’nsaw taht dna hguoht ffo delooc eh nehw mih no dnuora kcab elcric ylbaborp d’eH
,etoyoC triD yb ”selpmaS eerF“ saw sihT
.stops dlab s’lapicnirp eht no nwot ot gniog detrats uoy nehw yllaicepse
.ylikahs deksa eh "?derebmemer uoy-
”.ereh resol tseggib eht m’I ezilaer ot elpoep rof regnol sekat yllausu tsuJ .enif s’tI .tnaem uoy tahw wonk I .ti evaS“
”.ssalc ruo ni enoyreve detlusni
.htiw nigeb ot nosrep a sa mih was ylerab sremotsuc esuaceb dna ksoik eht fo retnuoc hgih tsiaw eht dniheb htob ,neddih llew saw eh wenk hajilE
,uoy tsuj t’nsaw ti ,oN“
,dooG !dooG“ ,gnicnuonna erofeb ylthgit rehtegot swap gnippalc ,teef sih no decnuob naeS ”.tif taerg a eb
,dias dna detrons hajilE ,deffubeR
,ffo ti deggurhs tsuj tub pals eht ta denworf naI
.ni sevoorg emos tuc I doow fo kcolb a tsuj saw tI“
,suoitecaf a tuo tel dna
ot noitnetta sih xif ot esle gnihtemos
”.taht retfa thgiarts keew a rof hgual t’ndluoc I“
kaeuqs a ni ffo tuc naI "—
,mih dniheb derettuts naI ”,yeh-
.sretsiger s’tnemtraped cinortcele eht gnidloh ksoik ralucric a ot revo mih del eh sa dias hajilE
.gurhs a htiw dekoj hajilE
,stluda eht neewteb noisufnoc ni pu dekool yob elttil ehT
,gnirumrum erofeb taorht siht ta spin dna sessik erom wef a tog hajilE
.ecnelis drawkwa eht kaerb ot tsrif eht saw hajilE dna
deeps lluf ta naI dna flesmih gnipmup saw eh ,hguoht setunim lareves retfA
s’naI ot wap a gnippals ,dias hajilE
”.hgual ruoy sa lufwa sa ton s’ti tsael tA .bmud ytterp saw’T“
”?hceeps eht retfa neve...em htiw
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
.elims kaew a mih gnivig ,deksa eh ”?doog eW“
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.ksa yeht reverehw ot meht tniop dna flesruoy rof kool tsuj uoY
.ecnamrofrep eht rof spalc elpuoc a mih gnivig ,dias hajilE
nooccar gniraew-sessalg yknal a doots ,renroc eht denrut eh sa ,erehT
Y“ .dnuorg eht gnicaf saw elzzum s’nooccar eht taht ees ot ylno ezag sih teem ot denrut hajilE
,ruos dren eht evael ot gnitnaw ton ,hajilE
.eciov s'naI gnitatimi ,setouq ria ni pu swap sih desiar dna
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.enif enif ,wO“
”.won ti tuoba gnikniht deticxe elttil a gnitteg adniK“
.elkcuhc a htiw detrats hajilE
.ylevisnefed tuo flesmih gninethgiarts ,worb sih deworruf naI ”.edud ,eciN
.dedlof smra sih htiw taps hajilE
N“ .redluohs sih hcnelc ot tsehc sih dnuora mra na depparw eh dna semit elpuoc a dehctiwt liat siH
.roolf eht ni skcarc eht gnola deloop dah tser eht elihw ,teliot eht ot gnignilc llits saw ti fo emoS
—m’I .resol a ton er’uoY
.yad doog a si sihT
.erp fo lraep a htiw denworc ria eht otni gnignirps ,raewrednu sih fo tuo decnuob kcoc s'naI
doots srae s’hajilE fo htoB
.taht ylpmi ot naem t’ndid I“
dna thgir leef t’ndid
gnihtyreve dedrocer enoemoS
.ewa ni kcab eht gniyduts erofeb mih gniknaht ,ylregnig xob eht koot ehS
,niaga deirt naI ,eciov sih ni ssenerus erom htiw tub ,yltnatiseH
,hU" "?drawtuo gnicaf si eltit eht os sgniht kcats ot woh wonk uoY"
?!ciffarT !?ciffarT“
.detcejretni hajilE
.laerec eht rof mih gniggeb saw buc sih erofeb elsia eht nwod yawflah ti edam ylerab flow deyonna ehT
”,timda ot evah I ,hguohT“
.dnuorg eht sdrawot eson ,derepmihw naI
.ylsuoregnad gnola deggat tnecs rieht hguoht ,wap ni wap rehtegot gniklaw ecnalg dnoces yna meht evag eno oN
,drah niaga deffins eh erofeb spil s’naI detrap rumrum wol das A
,enohp sih tuo dellup dna retsiger eht tsniaga pu denael eltsimocac ehT ".edud
",erots eht flah naht rekrow retteb a ydaerla er'uoY .emosewA" .dexelprep gnikool deilper nooccar eht "?haey
?gnola lla yag erew uoy-Y“ .ediw tnew seye sih dna
?ylsuoires ekat ot ereht s’tahW“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,ew eh erofeb tuo tel sbos nepo duol lareveS
.’ylimaF dna ,ytlucaF ,stnedutS otnI raeT ot hceepS noitaudarG sesU nairotcidelaV ssalC‘ !lariv tnew tI
.deyonna enot sih ,dias hajilE ”,ymmud
liat sih htiw sexob nezod a flah revo dekconk
”?ereh gniod I ma tahW“
.rekrowoc wen sih tuoba laicos sih no tsop a ffo gnidnes
”?tnemirepxe laicos a ebyam
,deksa dna ,desufnoc ,daeh sih dekcoc naI
”?deneppah tahW .reve —kcuf eht—
”?taht pord tsuj uoy dluoW“
hajilE ”!haey lleH“
.weiver ecnamrofrep a rof ni mih gnirb ll’yeht ,sdrac ydrat evif stcelloc eh fi nehT
.etal etunim a gnieb rof meht kcohs dluow taht ecived a htiw deppihc eb yllautneve dluow seeyolpme lla fi enoyna ot esirprus gib a eb t’ndluow tI
.sllaw doowylp niht eht epacse ot derad taht snaom laud dedrawer saw dna
.evif fo daetsni etal setunim net won
.thgirf ni sgel sih pu
”,syad eseht ciffart wonk uoy ,naeS yrroS“
,nosinu ni dias yeht
elzzum s’nooccar eht ta thgir slewot repap fo sdaw gniworht nugeb dah hajilE ”!potS
.sdrawretfa emac taht rethgual gniknoh suoedih s’eivaD hajilE saw ecarg gnivas ylno ehT .emit eno taht swap ym fo tuo skoob ym gnippals rof dooW rehpotsirhC kcuf dnA“
.wap reh gnidloh ddot elttil reh htiw yb deklaw nexiv a ,deksa eh sa tsuJ
.did eh nehw yawa detfihs seye sih dna
ot detnaw taht eno eht er'uoY"
.1202 fo
yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw
.saw eh sa deticxe sa tsuj ,stnap sih ni dehctiwt tI
,feiler fo hgis a tuo tel hajilE
.kcar eht bmilc ot yrt dluoc ehs erofeb ni deppets ylitsah eh ,laerec fo xob a rof gnihcaer buc flow a gnittopS
.tsap eht ni saw
,htaerb sih gnihctac saw dna kcab daeh sih nworht dah nooccar ehT
,rellevarT wolleF ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
a saw I thguoht enoyrevE
os eb ot evah uoy oD“
yllaer ton m'I ,foo ,d'I .tihs ,hO"
"?ssalg eht dniheb ffuts eht roF ?yek A"
.’kloflliH‘ ,dias uoy sa ,su gnoma yag ylno eht t’nerew uoy tub ,naI ,hsalf sweN“
.spil sih ot regnif a yb ffo tuc saw naI "—a adnik si siht—
”.em tsuj saw ti thguoht I
.syart fo elbat a revo deldduh
...oot nuf saw bojdnah eht dnA
.toh os saw ti
foor eht no bmilc nac I
.swap sih ni ti tpek dna trac eht htaenrednu morf liat sih tuo dellup hajilE
,syawyna ti dootsrednu evah t’ndluow eH
.hgual a dekrab hajilE ”?naI“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.detpure tsev s’etaicossa nwo sih ni esuom nootrac a ”!ho hU“
?taht tnaw d’ohW .mih gnirif
.yleerf erp tuo depmup taht sekorts wols gnol ni kcoc sih debbur hajilE
,rO“ .elcric flah a ni dnuora detfihs dna swap sih dednetxe hajilE ”?gnihtemos ro ekoj a siht sI“ ”?selpmas eerF“
”?ti si ,melborp a eb annog toN .yag m’I ,haeY“
,pil sih ot hteet kcub sih desserp naeS
.meht neewteb ecnelis eht dellif daehrevo srekaeps no ylsseldne gnitaeper elgnaj elgnij evisneffo-non eht revo ylerusiel yb gnillorts strac gnippohs fo sdnuoS
.spil sih fo srenroc eht ta gnigreme elims a tsniaga thguof eh dna hgih dehcra erew sworbeye siH
.meht pots ,sVT ledom roolf eht fo eno ekat ot seirt ssakcaj emos nehw dna"
,gniunitnoc erofeb eson sih morf gnilgnad tons fo bolg egral a ni detrons naI ”,yrros m’I“
.esuap a saw erehT
”.ylsuoires gnihtyna ekat reven uoY“
.edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc dna denworf naI ”?eniM“
”?em tuoba dias uoy tahw rebmem‘ ,yeH“
”?ecneics tekcor dna sehcaeb ot deneppah tahw oS“
,ffo mih tuc hajilE
”.ereh revo ekat nac ehs os adnariM barg oG
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
?gnitcepxe uoy erew tahW" "?ti s'tahT"
.ylevixelfer srae s’dinycorp
.enilno ti dedaolpu dna
.hguorht dehsup tub ,deil hajilE
.sgod toh devaworcim tuo gnissap rekaB naI dessim evah dluow hajilE
,levon a gnitirw si
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
snoitanalpxe tsednik s’nooccar ehT
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.ni dna tuo demoob tsehc sih sa ylduol gnipmuht draeh eb dluoc traeh s'nooccar ehT
.seye moordeb tseb sih mih evag hajilE
”.pu gniworg etirovaf ym erew esohT .sekalF ocoC“
gnittes eht tsuj neve ro ,hceeps eht ,oiranecs eht
”.loohcs eht ni enoyreve ffo dlot uoY
.htaenrednu elit eht tsniaga delaeuqs seohs sih elihw flesmih ydaets ot taes teliot eht ot swap htob deppirg naI
.kcab eht hguorht mih del eltsimocac eht sa tib eno nwod mih wols ot demees stsetorp sih fo enoN ".emit
.etal syawlA .etaL“
”,em fo daetsni mih ta gnihgual saw enoyreve ezilaer ot esned oot saw hajilE dnA
.slirtson sih fo tuo gnikrow ydaerla tons
.yldnilb tnemtraped sih sdrawot degdurt eh ,erots eht otni tuo deppets eh sA
”,lla ta degnahc t’nevah uoY“
”.ylrae yaw eht fo tuo hceeps gib ruoy teg nac uoy os mocretni eht krow ot woh uoy wohs tsuj nac I ebyaM“
.dnoces a rof tsael ta ,pu mih tuhs ot hguone saw reganam sih fo lrans railimaf prahs ehT ”!hajilE“ ”.won thgir siht deen t’nod I .og dna elpmas eht ekat tsuJ“
noitseuq eht htiw pu gnimrots saw naeS tnemom tcaxe taht tA
.gnisitsahc latigid eromyna teg ot tnaw t’ndid eh fi worromot ylrae pu wohs ot flesmih dednimer dna seye sih dellor eH
.elsi eht dellif owt eht neewteb gnirekciB
.hu huN“ .srae dna smra sih ta staws gnitnelernu tub thgil htiw mih detluassa eh
noisivelet txen ruoy pu tes yllanosrep ll’I taht ris uoy erussa I“
”!ma’aM .hsog ho—ahw tsaL“
tahW“ ”.ecneics retupmoC“
ezeeuqs a nooccar eht dna flesmih htob evag eh ,pil sih gnitiB .erusaelp ni lriws dnim sih edam taht mih rof sgniht did
dna roolf eht ffo pu gnitteg ,dehgis eH
”—uf mub elttil ruoy tih ot hguone raf kcor a worht dna
.emit eht lla ,syawynA" ,dias nooccar eht ,pu gninethgiL
.wap derevoc zzij eht ta kcil a evag dna
.sreksihw tneb s’nooccar eht revo lla nettirw erusaelp gniees
sehtolc sih dniheb kcab ylkciuq dekcut saw ruf etihw kciht
em htiw krow dluow eno oN
,tniop emos ta cim eht tuc evah dluohs yllaer yeht ,haey ,hcT“
”,luferac erom eB“
roloc fo deniard ecaf s’naI
.moorhtab eht tuo gnimrots dna dnuora gninnips
dna noitces siht morf smeti s’elpoep pu gnir si od attog uoy llA .tenalp eht no boj tseisae eht si sihT
.xaler ot hguone pu mih desae redluohs sih no gnitser wap esirprus A
strohs sih deppord hajilE ,roolf elit yemirg eht gnidnim toN
.edisni pu tliub erusserp eht fo emos gniveiler yllautca eno siht
”!ahahahahahayN“ ,ylacinem kcab daeh sih werht dna tuhs eson sih dehcnip hajilE ,dehsinif eh
,tnemssarrabme ni elzzum sih pu derevoc naI
,ni kcolc ot hajilE dewolla ti ,stpmorp eht gnihsinif yllaniF
gnihcaorppa yltfiws dna
htob kcud ot hguone prahs saw tI
.flesmih deticxe gnitteg saw eh fi ro cilbup os saw ti esuaceb fi erus t’nsaw eh ,toh gnitteg saw nooccar eht yaw eht htiW
,detcepxe evah thgim naI yhtapmys eht fo daetsnI
noitartsurf ni dnuora kcab gninrut ,ti koot eH
”gnihtyreve dna hceeps elooooooohw a daH
.retnuoc eht nwod knuls eh sa spil s’naI tuo depacse enihw dehctip hgih gnol A
.esab s’teliot eht tsniaga derettalps tohs tsrif sih sa
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,goD fo ecioV ehT no
,tuo saw eh nehw dna
.seenk sih ot tog eh sa
H“ .retnuoc eht revo deklus eh sa hguoht lufwa tlef llits mih fo traP
.mih ta gnimoc swap eht yawa dettaws ylbeef eh sa deggeb naI ”,pots tsuJ
,delbmum naI ,seenk sih no gnitser waj sih htiw ,woN
ssalc ni peelsa llef ehs nehw knip stops etihw s’eod a detniap ew emit taht tegrof uoy dluoc woH“
.gel sih dnuora depparw dah liat gnol sih dna kcab dedlof erew srae siH
.ylsuoituac naI revo gnikool ,detrats eh ”,railimaf er’eW“
.hctorc sih ot regnif a dehcuot dna strohs sih ot nwod wap a decart eH
,deksa eh sa yllufemahs nwod elzzum sih tpek naI
”.elbuort hcum os ni teg ot desu eW ?pohsdooW rebmemeR .niaga srentrap er’ew ekil skool ,oS“
.flehs a no noisivelet hcni 54 a gulpnu ot gniyrt esoom a ot revo gnicar ,teef sih ot depmuj hajilE "!riS
.flehs eht gnikcatser elihw derettum hajilE
kcik ot xnyl ybraen a gnitteg ,demialcxe
eno siht piks esaelp
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.sgniht gnikcats er'uoy ekil kool ro tihs gnipiw trats dna gar a barg ,dnuora semoc naeS fI
.ylduol detrons dna eralghtaed a naI evag ehS
”?neeb uoy evah kcuf eht erehW“
,sedis eht nwod dellor sporD
,mih dniheb tuoba gnilffuhs nooccar eht raeh dluoc eH
neercs eht morf deppord seman fo golatac A
”,hcT“ a htiw ffo ti deggurhs hajilE
”.tnemtraped ruoy rof etaicossa wen a evah eW
noitcerid s’erah eht ni eralg yldaed A .elzzum sih no
,esoht fo nezod a tuoba retfA
,tcatnoc eye edam yehT
”,trap ym gniod tsuJ“
.ylwols tuo ti gnittel erofeb elahni peed
.ti fo elddim eht gnirud tuo ’nimoc uoy saw tegrof t’ndid I tahW“
.remotsuc ylurnu eht htiw ecneitap s'dren eht ta desuma
.srekcins ylasan dna sknoh htiw tnemtraped rieht gnillif owt eht ot skool ddo evag sremotsuC
.debircsed sa yltcaxe hgual nooccar eht ekam ot hguone ynnuf
,remotsuc eht detlah eltsimocac eht nehw nevE
.hturt eht t’nsaw taht gniwonk ,deksa eh
,delworg dna tsehc s’eltsimocac eht otni regnif a gnikcits ,deppots naI
.dnim ym egnahc I erof‘ ,dren ,pu tuhS"
”,boj siht etah ’nikcuF“ ”.spoO“
.setunim evif yreve eno ekat hcae uoy ,raews I
",hO
.syob dab eseht fo eno nrut ot woh wonk uoy ,woN"
.retsaf ylthgils os reve kcoc sih fo pit eht tem tfahs sih fo esab eht morf detrats taht ekorts yrevE
.selsi eht nwod ecap reh pu dekcip nexiv eht sa tuo taps hajilE
.htiw laed ot ssenisub retteb dah eh fi sa ffo gniklaw erofeb
dnif ot gniyrt ,ylsuovren dnuora dekool eH
”,nedloG CU ta ekoj
”,spit lufpleh emos s’ereH
.sregnif sih ffo gninaelc eltsimocac eht ees ot elbanu
.kcen s’rehto eht otni sgnaf gniknis saw eh erofeb mih dniheb esolc rood moorhtab eht tel yldrah hajilE
.naI ta pu gnikool ,dekramer hajilE ”,dab toN“
.tuo dellac eciov yllasan a ”!selpmas eerF“
dlruW niagraB a fo moorhtab eht ni ecneirepxe lauxes tsrif ym gnitteG
syaw wen gnipoleved syawla saw ynapmoc eht tub ,wor a ni syad eerht etal saw eh taht emit tsal gniyonna siht gnieb ti rebmemer t’ndid eH
",wooooooooooW“ .ykahs tlef osla tub
naI denokceb eh ,strohs ograc sih htaenrednu bmuht a htiW
,lworg wol a evag remotsuc eht ,trac sih dehcaorppa eh sa tsuJ
,flehs a tsniaga pu depmuls naI
stnecs rof gniffins ,kcarc eht tuo dekop elzzum rednels s’eltsimocac ehT .yamsid s’hajilE ot ylision delaeuqs ecnartne moorkaerb ehT etoyoC triD yB
,derepsihw dna ni denael ,deyonna ,nooccar ehT
"?em gniniart erew uoy
.gel sih dnuora ylesool delioc liat sih ,erots eht fo noitces sih sdrawot yaw sih dekrow eh sA
,trihs derekcehc egnaro eveels gnol a revo tsev setaicossa wolley ylgu emas eht gniraew saw eH
uoy er’tahw ,tiaW“
.tniop wol gnikcuf ruoy ton m’I .yddub ,yaw gnikcuf oN
.dessorc smra sih ,detroter naI
.wap s’hajilE revo elddup a gnivael ,tfahs nwo sih no nwod kcab thgir dednal tsoM
.ytrap ytip eht pots ,hO“
.nwod deggut erew sfeirb sih dna deppiznu saw reppiz sih yllanif litnu
,denihw eh ”,taht dias I
,mih fo tuo knups sih fo stib tsal eht dexaoc eh sa mrif deniamer pirg siH
,tuo denaorg eh ,naI ot gninruT
.sevolg fo tes nwo sih no gnittup erah repyh eht yb elbat eht dniheb tuo devohs saw naI
,nwod flesmih gnimlaC
.niaga etal er’uoy ekil skooL“
rebmemer ot dnoces a naI koot tI
,thgis eht erimda ot dnoces a gnikaT
”?seivaD hajilE gnikcuf morf
.mra sih ta debbur eh dna naI morf pley esirprus a tog tahT
”,ni gniklaw saw I sa kaerb a no reh waS“
edis eno sdrawot gninael ylismulc erew ecaf sih no sessalg ehT
erofeb tsev s’etaicossa sih tuo gnillup ,rekcol sih ot revo deklaw dna edisni deppils eh ,raelc tsaoc eht htiW
.kcoc sih morf dettej muc fo epor wen a emit hcae flesmih elfits ot elbanu ,ylduol naI morf depacse erusaelp fo snaoM
.pets txen sih gnirednop ylsuovren
,evisnefed erom tog eltsimocac eht dna elffins rehtonA
.dedlocs remotsuc eht
,gninraw erofeb owt eht neewteb ecnalg drawnwod a derahs erah ehT
yrros ylbirret os ,os m’I“
.deppans naI ”?yhcuot
",reggib dat a ylbaborp m'I kniht I ,mmmH" .elims suoived a htiw tnemwodne s'nooccar eht dezis eltsimocac eht
.nairotcidelav ssalc ym saw eH ?wonk uoy t’noD“
.yliratnemom eltsimocac eht detneirosid thgil tnecseroulf thgirB
.daeh sih denrut eh dna pu dekrep srae s’naI
.dnuorg eht gnicaf elzzum sih htiw denihw eh ",em tih t'nod ,yeH"
eltsimocac eht
ll’eH” —nooccar gnikool elbatrofmocnu eht ot kniw a dessap eh—
.meht fo owt eht neewteb mhtyhr ydaets a gnitteg ,mednat ni swap htob dekrow eH
.rekaB naI taerg ehT
,gninraw a neeb ev’thgim taht gnihtemos tuo tel eh dna
thguoht I" .deyonna ,deksa hajilE "?tahW"
.lesaew a morf trons a dna eralg a tog tsuj eh ,ygolopa na fo daetsni tub ,niap ni pley a tuo tel eH
”,yegac os emaceb uoy ,loohcs hgih detrats ew ecno ,zeeJ"
.tfahs sih fo esab eht deppirg hajilE sa thgir
.reh revo denael dna xob egral eht dehctans eH
.elzzum sih pu tperc elims suoiruc a dna
.srae sih pu dekcilf dna ecnats evisnefed sih nwod tel nooccar eht ,ylevitiziuQ ".seivom if-ics toiR guoD bmud dehctaw dna sdrac gninokceR ehT :nomeD deyalp uoy esuaceb enoyreve ta nwod gnikool puorg dren ruoy ni kcuts tsuj erew uoY
norpa sih revo dednah nooccar ehT
.ssa sih no talf tsomla saw eh litnu knis nooccar eht did
.ylevitcerroc hctaw tsirw sih ta deppat eh dna worb sih ffo gnulf taews fo spord dezis yllacimoC
.yromem nwo sih deggoj eh sa yldeticxe selcric ni wap a devaw hajilE
.redluohs sih deppat dna drawrof dehcaer
.spitregnif s’eltsimocac eht gnola sliart ykcits gnivael
.dnuora saw eno on ,yletanutroF
rotinom hcni 06 a elppot ot ydaer tar ylredle na sdrawot decar eh sa tuo deirc naI
erofeB ”.skcart niart ot namow a gniyt dehsinif tog tsuj uoy ekil sdnuos hgual ruoY ?suoires uoY“
.sevlehs eht no dekcats
.ees ot evol dna raeh ot ekil I tahw yltcaxe s’tahT
.moorhtab a ni taht od dluoc I fi onnud I ,oslA
gnirettum wol ot flesmih peek dna edisni ti dloh saw od dluoc eh llA
.htaerb rof gnipsag ylralimis morf peek t’ndluoc dna
?ot emoc sah efil ym tahw siht si ,tsuj s’ti“
.yalpsid eht htaenrednu sexob eht fo eno ekat ylpmis ot dedaussid yletaidemmi eb t’ndluoc nam redlo eht
”.sepor eht mih wohS .og tsuJ
s’eltsimocac ehT .ria eht ot desopxe eh ruf cibup eht ta kool ot
”.won no sucof rehtar d’I
uoy litnu gniog peek uoy tel tsuj yeht ,epoN
.stnemercni ynit ni ecap sih denekciuq eh ,yllaudarG
?gniod uoy er’tahW !yeH
.nwod mih gnirats flow a sdrawot deklaw hajilE sa reh detcartsid selddir dna selzzuP
.tey mih retsep ot gniog t’nsaw naeS taht dalg tsael ta
tcaer ot hguone desserpmi erew rehtieN .noihsaf ad-
.tlah a ot gnihceercs mih tnes
.ylyls dias eltsimocac eht ",ecaf saremac on taht sesu eno on moorhtab a s'ereht ,wonk uoY"
.yaw sih ni enoyna tsap gnihsup
.edud ,pu nethgil ,hO"
,epaga tnew wam s'naI ".ksa
.teliot eht no nwod mih tnalp ot eltsimocac eht dewolla naI dna kcirt eht od ot demees tahT ".dnim
,dehctaw eh sa delims hajilE
.mih ot txen tops a gnikat ,dehgual hajilE ”!gniyas m’I tahw s’tahT“
.htiw revo siht teg s’teL .enif ,eniF"
swap sih gnidloh ,dessih naI
".hceeps ruoy dehsinif uoy retfa thgir ti enod evah d'I ,tsaf os ffo ekat t'ndid uoy fi ,kceH
yllautca fo kniht thgim yeht
.ereht thgir remotsuc eht tuo wehc ot ton ygrene sih fo lla koot tI
.flehs eht ffo thgir
.retnec tnemniatretne sih rof ezis tcaxe eht saw ti taht erus saw eh esuaceb
.drac ydrat a mih teg
.esrow sgniht ekam ot
.eromyna naI tuoba dab sa etiuq gnileef t’nsaw eh ,remotsuc eht dna erah eht neewteb tilps regna sih htiW
flow eht nehw elsi eht fo tuo tsomla ,yawa denrut hajilE
sih fo srumrum elttil tuo gnittel dna ylideerg tnecs s'rehto eht ni gnikat
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,derettum dna naI otni nael hajilE did renroc eht denrut remotsuc eht retfa dnoces a neve toN
.rehtegotla ffo ti dellup eh erofeb redluohs sih no pu gnisnet wap s’naI
”,vorpmi saw taht fo tsom dna shtnom neeb s’tI .on-
”.evlos t’ndluoc eh taht rehcaet eht evag uoy xob elzzup eht ro
.lian a morf gnignah yek a tuo dellup dna htaenrednu dehcaer eH
saw noitatimi nwo s’hajilE
”,niaga hgual reve d’I kniht t’ndid I ,edud kcuF“ ”?keew A“
.nooccar eht gnihcaorppa ,elkcuhc a htiw deksa hajilE
—saw I thguoht I !em dlot eno oN
.erots eht otni gnidael srood elbuod eht tuo yaw sih dekrow dna tsev sih no tup hajilE ,gnilbmurG
nehw 'sdubrae eseht dnemmocer ylhgih I' yas yllanoisacco
.yadot em ot siht gniod ton er’uoY .yadot toN“
”?gnihtemos ro dloc
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
yldrawkwa rehtona eno tsniaga thguof swap rieht dna gnipleh deirt naI
.elbigilletni eb ot delffum oot
,dias dna ,edis eht sdrawot srae sih dekcilf hajilE ”.doog er’ew ,haeY“
.oot em rof tuo ti dah srosseforp dna
,eciov sih rof ton fI
.gninnigeb eht morf revo trats dluow ti
,ksam kcalb sih dna kcid s’naI neewteb derahs saw ezag s’hajilE
.teef sih ot pu kcab dna dnuorg eht ffo flesmih dehsup yob nooccar eht erofeb ecneitap sih esol ot tuoba saw eH
derutaef yrots siH
.elzzum s’nooccar eht depacse elkcuhc A
".eno tsal eht fo erac koot I esuac ,emosewA"
.drawpu gnitniop wap sih ,desaet eh ",ysae s'tahT"
.tsrif ta mih ezingocer ot mees t’ndid nooccar eht tub
,deef sih hguorht dellorcs neht eH
.hsulf saw ti fi gnirac ton ,flehs eht no xob tsal eht deffuts ylkciuq hajilE .lleh
”,tif t’nseod eno siht fi
a tog uoy ,kcuf ehT“
!skaerb no syawlA“ .drah waptoof enipal egral sih depmats dna pu smra sih werht naeS
.siht ekil gnihtyna enod d'eh ecnis etunim a neeb d'tI .nwo
”.tenalp eht no boj tseisae ,ssakcaj lanoisacco eht naht rehto ,eeS“
?eciton naeS t'noW
”.thgin tsal rennid rof eta I tahw rebmemer ylerab I
.yawa gninrut dna smra sih gnidlof ,naI morf ffuh a tog tahT .desaet
”,syawyna ti togrof I ,haeY“
.meht ees dluoc enoyna fi gnirednow
.htuom gib ym dna em was elpoep fo sdnasuoht fo sderdnuH
.noitces sih sdrawot yawa mih del hajilE sa
nossel eht fo daeha piks ot deirt dna ecneitap sih tsol hajilE emit yrevE
.deunitnoc eh sa seye sih gnibbur ,denihw naI
,dias dna dehgual tsuj hajilE
.trac sih edisni ti gnivohs yltnatculer erofeb
.nruter on fo tniop eht
”.ssel on tnemtraped ym nI
hajilE ",deggarb uoy sa trams sa ton er'uoy sseug I
”.raey eromohpos ecnis moorhtab muisanmyg eht ni sbojdnah tuo gnissap saw I wenk enoyrevE
"?em rof noitseuq a sah remotsuc a fi tahW ?si gnihtyreve erehw em wohs annog uoy t'nerA" .tuo
”selpmaS eerF“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
rehtruf dna rehtruF
”.ti tnaw annog s’ehs woN .ssakcaj sknahT“
daerb ot noitnetta sih gninrut nam eht
,hajilE morf desaeler hgis gnol rehtonA
,ygolopa nwo sih deirt eh ,mih ta gnikool ton llitS
.roolf eht no tfel d’eh ssem eht ta decamirg dna nwod dekool hajilE
.sretaw eht tset d'eh sseuG
”.ssakcaj ,sisirc neet etal ruoy ton m’I
pu ti gninaelc esle enoemos tuoba gniknihT
”—naem I ,ylpmi ot naem t’ndid I“
.ffurcs keehc yarg sih rednu demossolb der dna knip fo sedahS
.hceeps noitaudarg suomafni eht gnirud tuo tuohs elttil nwo sih tog eh ecnis yllaicepse ,nwodkaerb eht gnihctaw dnim t’ndid hajilE
,meht ni etib emos dah sdrow siH
,naI tuoba gnihtemoS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.wap hcae revo sevolg xetal dah dna
,gnimrifnoc yb etouq sih detautcnup eh
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
,emac reven gnitcepxe saw eh ygolopa ehT
.trac reh edisni VT eht tif ot gnilggurts tar nrobbuts eht yb dessimsid erew
.msagro nwo sih fo dne eht ta og gnittel ylno
.liat gnihsal sih revo nar remotsuc a erofeb ereht yawflah ti edam ylnO
,deksa dna elzzum sih denepo eh erofeb taorht sih ni pmul egral a nwod dekohc plug duol rehtonA
.seye sih fo srenroc eht fo tuo deknilb erew dna pu tliub dah sraeT
.edisni senohpdaeh evisnepxe lareves htiw esac a ta detniop
.pils gninraw a teg ll’eh dna swohs etal erom owT
flesmih did eh sa naI rof ylerus sa tsuj ti wenk eH
ffuts od ot detnaw uoY“
.thgiled fo ooc tfos eht htiw decalper saw ti litnu ylduol gnittehcocir ,sllaw eht tsniaga decnuob plug A
”?siht si kcuf ehT“
.ksoik sih fo ytefas eht otni kcab ti edam yllanif sa
.ni elttes ti tel neve dluoc eh erofeb wolgretfa sih dellik
.sessalg sih niheb pu demaets goF
.elzzum sih tfel bos tsrif eht erofeb tib eno pu flesmih naelc ot derehtob t’ndah eH
.snoicipsus sih mrifnoc ot deticxe
ledom roolf eht barg ot tnaem eh taht deugra eH
.eltsimocac eht ot eye knits eht gnivig erofeb ton tub ,ffo detoocs eH
.daerd htiw gnillif traeh ,deksa hajilE ”?gniod
.gnignah sngis eht lla ees uoY"
.tuo eugnot sih kcuts dna ylgnisaet mra eht no mih deppals tsuj hajilE
.dnuora kcab nups dna depmuj eH
.daeh sih koohs dna detrons hajilE
.krej a saw I thguoht ,ekoj a saw I kniht t’ndid taht esohT“
.mih fo tnorf ni tleb eht denesool eh emit emas eht strohs sih ta deregnif hajilE ,ylkciuq gnikroW
.eglub s'naI fo eniltuo eht gnola walc a decart eH
.eciov eltsihw elttek a ni dias eh
?thguac tog ew fi tahW"
”,roivaheb roop ruoy htiw etaicossa wen ruo lios ton esaelp uoy dluoC
”—t’nod esaelp ,on kcuf ,wA“
”,stoidi gnilbmub uoy morf yawa selim 003,2“ ”?ti tup uoy did woh ,llew ,ekil ,eb ot desoppus uoy t’nerA“
raeh ot desoppus t'nsaw eh drow tahw tuo erugif ot gniyrt
.trac sih htaenrednu xob eht gnikcut ,dias hajilE
.srae sih thguac elffins a erofeb krow ot teg ot ydaer tuoba saw dna kcab dellorts eh ,resnepsid a morf slewot wef a gnibbarG
,mih dniheb gniltsur emos sdrawot daeh sih gninrut ,desuap eh
.daeh sih pu dekcilf eh kciuq woh htiw tuons sih ffo deppop ylraen sessalg s'naI
”,taht ezilaer ot setunim net mih kooT
.woW ?ereh skrow yllautca eh oS“
.niaga nwod kaerb ot ydaer gnikool
”.did I yaw eht gnitcaer rof yrros m’I
sgniht ym dekcap I .em ot tog tsuj erusserp ehT
.nwo sih fo hgual gniknoh eniuneg
.seciov rof gninetsil dna
.kaeps ot egaruoc eht pu dekrow eh sa taorht s’naI edisni gnilgrug plug kciht eht thguac hajilE
",daor eht pu yajraT a s'ereht ,yssalc erehwemos detnaw uoy fI .ydneW ,dlruW niagraB a s'tI"
.desucof tpek eh tub ,hajilE morf elkcuhc a tog tahT ”.doog yllaer sleef sihT“ ,derepsihw dna nihc sih no loord epiw ot wap a pu dehcaer eh ,dnim sih daer dluoc naI fi sA
.rethgual fo tif a otni gnitpure erofeb dnoces a rof rehtona eno ta ylknalb derats owt ehT
”—gnihton-rof-doog yzal rehtona derih I fi won em llet ll’uoy ,yeH“
”selpmaS eerF“   yojne esaelP