,htaerb sih no lohocla eht llems I
,nam fo setsat eh lla fo tsom tuB
,htuom sih etsat I
.rebos eb llits ot dneterp t’nac I dna
,pu enil smhtyhr ruO
yebba eht ot kcab yaw eht lla knom neknurd a deklats ecno
.engapmahc tub hcamots sih ni gnihton htiw reciffo cinoelopaN a fo daeh eht ffo koot ,swalc sih fo wolb eno htiw ,rehtaf s’rehtaf yM
”.emit tsrif eht thguoht I tahw s’taht ,tsael tA“
.nehcaA fo vuakhaB ehT ma I
.swodahs eht otni repeed mih llup I
.kcab sih no em seirrac eH
,risavK fo syad eht ecnis ,susynoiD fo syad eht ecnis nem neknurd no gniyerp neeb sah dnik yM
?nem eseht htiw tuo gnah dna rab eht ot pu wohs
,dael sih swollof em tsniaga thgit mih gnippirg t’nsi taht wap ehT
.srae ym no ruf tfos eht sehctarcs
,tsehc ym dnif sdnah siH .eugnot sih
.siht ekil nem rof tiaw ni eil I
.galf wobniar eht htiw eno ehT
.denraelnu eb nac
.seilper eh ”,t’nevah uoY“
.taorht ym fo kcab eht selkcit ti sa tnemeticxe sih fo tlas eht etsat I
.mih htiw enod ton m’I tuB .gnorts yrev m’I
.ecnatsid eht otni sedaf gnignis ehT
?eparg eht dna niarg morf gnitteg ot desu era dnik sih taht rednerrus citatsce fo dnik emas eht ni tub ,raef ni ton
.yrlever neknurd ni slarom rieht gniddehs
,gnola lla taht nwonk ev’I ,siht
,yrots eritne na htiw aidem laicos no skramer eldi s’ikahK fo eno ot
.era ew ereh dna snrut wef A
”.dnaloR“ ,mih llet I oS
snoisacco esoht no suoveirg erom si tI
.swoble sih ot spord eH
floWcaM boR yb dna
.eugnot sih no gniregnil llits dees ym etsat I .redneT .wols s’tI
.esrow si dezilanretni
.su htiw knird a evah dna ni emoc dluoc uoy ,emit txen“
ekil nem eseht tuB
?em ekil yllautca yeht dluoc tub
,no derif saw rehtomdnarg taerg yM
.seye ym nepo I
,srorepmE namoR yloH fo snoitanoroc eht ot smirglip tnalibuj deruoved ohw
.ediskcab sih tsniaga drah sserp spih yM
.taorht sih tuo erot dna
,siht did em erofeb srotsecna ym lla fI
,nrut a dna esruc kciuq A
.rebos ro knurd s’eh rehtehw
”.tem ew tsal ecnis …degnahc ev’uoY“
,kcab erab sih tsniaga stser
”.laer t’nerew uoy detcepxe flah I“ .rrup I
.stnaw eh tahw dlot eb ot deen t’nod I
,gnafecI yb daeR
.dnabtsiaw mined eht ta gniggut swalc kciht eht
.tnerehocni gnihtemos gnignis ylduol
.swalc ym morf knalc sriats latem ehT
.lla retfa retsnom a m’I
.yawyella eht sessap dna sessorc puorg eht sa wodahs tsekrad eht otni yltnelis em edils swap yM
niaga seye ym esolc I
.tsehc sih ot daeh ym sserp ot
emoh yaw ruoy no ,er’uoy nehw ro
,did ti fi tuB ?ti t’nseoD
.em sdnuorrus htmraw dna htaerb riehT
?knird llits lla yeht od yhw neht
.hguone tsuj ,swodahs eht fo tuo pets I .retsnom a m’I
,thgiew ym tfihs I sa
,eugnot ym no gnilbmert
.srednepsus sih ffo gurhs dna
.htaerb sih fo llaf dna esir cimhtyhr eht gniwollof
.gniyas flesym dnif I
”.gnihtemos ro liame na evah I
.paeh a ni mih fo ffo llaf sresuort sih raeh I
.ereh sgnirps toh eht ni gnillewd ydaerla erew ew
.erised gnihca sih nwod eugnot ym nur I nehw spsag eh dna
.yella eht fo ssenkrad eht morf reep seye delipup-tils yM
.klawedis eht gnihcraes seye
.yas dluow rehtaf ym ,gnitsugsiD
.toh ylhsirevef tsomla ,digir ,draH
.enim dnif spil siH .regnuh I
?won thgir em fo duorp eb rehtaf
.pu teg t’nseod nam ehT
.htaerb gnitnap sih ,mih llems nac I
,drawrof selbmuts eh dna nwod mih tup I
.pu mih kcip I sa ediw og seye siH .hguoht ,ereh toN
.kcab emac eno fi neppah dluow tahw deredisnoc reven I
.yawyella eht fo htuom gnipag eht ot kcab
.evird lamirp on ,ycnegru oN
ytilibarenluv tsetaerg sih fo leef ehT ?siht dna
yenoh detnemref ot snoitibihni dna ecnaligiv rieht pu evag tsrif snamuh eht ecnis
flesti decnivnoc os yteicos ruo taht
.seenk dna sdnah sih otno
,er’yeht nehw ,wonk uoy
.em fo duorp m’I tuB  .ton ylniatreC
gnihtolc latrom fo sgnippart eht edisa gnihsurb ylisae
,ebyam secnad ro
krad eht ni syad rof derutrot eh remraf a tuoba no tnew rehtaf yM
.stnialpmoc on sah eh tuB
.ees neve t’nac ylbaborp eH
,swodahs eht hguorht elbmuts mih hctaw I nehw
gnorw suoveirg a si tI
.ynam woh serac ohw
ev’ohw nem eht fo emos teem yllautcA
hself sih ruoved llits ll’I ,hO
.htaerb sih rednu snaom tniaf tceted srae ym dna
.htaerb ym fo mhtyhr eht etapocnys retaw gnippird fo seohcE
,selbmuts ro ,sklaw eH
,segru esab rieht ot ni gniviG
.tuo stug sih gniraet erofeb
,engamelrahC fo stsaef eht retfa sreitruoc deklats ohw srehtaferof ehT
”!uoy teem ot tnaw ll’yehT !enif s’tI
,nem neknurd htiw strilf tI
,si aibohpreeuq lanretxe sa dab sA
.eye ruoy hctac ot woh wonk ot detnaw wef a naht eroM
.ereht dloh dna mih edisni peed flesym yrub I emit eht yb gnitnap s’eH
.slirtson ym ni stroffe ruo fo taews gniyrd-ylwols eht
,eno emas eht ro ,esrev wen a gnignis er’yehT
,drah yrev os ,drah llits s’eH
.retsnom a m’I .duorp yreV
.srotsecna ym rof melborp a reven saw tI
,floWcaM boR dna seirraH nomoloS yb
,smret ym no ti od I tuB
,tnemom a semoc erehT
”xiA fo tsaeB eht ot sweN dooG eht thguorB yehT woH“ saw sihT.sretsnom
.meht htiw ,dehtaehs swalc ym peek syawla I
,snepo ti sa kaerc A
.won kcab ym gnihctarcs era sregnif siH
.tsaf gnihtaerb llitS
.drawrof pets rehtona sekat eH
”!dekrow ecivda ym yas ot yad txen eht kcab emac wef a naht eroM
,retsnom eht fo thgiew eht morf detsuahxe oot semoceb nam roop eht nehW
.mih nihtiw flesym dneps I sa raor wol a tuo tel dna
.ylwols snruter ssensuoicsnoC
.gnihton tih yeht esruoc fO
.swodahs eht ni gnitiaw tsaeb eht drawoT
.gnillik naht yrovas erom si sihT
,no dednuof yldesoppus saw ytic siht sgnirps toh eht ekil
.kaeps t’nod yllausu yehT
,rof hcrot siht gniyrrac neeb ev’I“ ,syas eh
.elttil a sekahs gel yM
,tlep ym ni sevlesmeht yrub sregnif siH
.erofeb ekil ton s’ti tuB
eb d’ti ,llew ,did yeht fi demussa I
.sevlesruo su decnivnoc ti
tsuj dluoc I taht hguonE
traeh ekat su tel tuB
.daeh gnidlab desopxe na ot pu seog dnah a ,retal spets neT
,snoissap lamina rieht niartser ,rebos yats yeht
,sdraknurd eht skcatta taht tsaeb eht raef yeht fI
.ssenkrad eht drawot ,nekat pets A
,tsurht mih leef I
htaerb sih no lohocla eht llems nac I
,nwod peed ,nosrep emas eht si nam a ebyaM
.gnirons strats meht fo enO
.kcen sih ta ffins ot redluohs sih revo sehcaer tuons ym
,seod syawla ereht
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.srednepsus ,draeB
hself sih sruoved ti neht
,niap ni ton
,oga gnol od ot desoppus saw I tahw tuoba gnirac pu evag I tuB
?knird a dah s’eh ecno gnieb tnereffid a semoceb nam a fi sA“ ”.knurd
.sehcrot dna skrofhctip lla
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
”xiA fo tsaeB eht ot sweN dooG eht thguorB yehT woH“
.si ti kniht yeht ymene eht t’nsi noissap lamina ebyaM
.seirutnec rof steerts eseht deklats evah srotsecna yM
.selttob dna sexob azzip ytpme eht revo thgil gnirekcilf a gnitsac llits si eldnac enol enO
,tekcaj rehtael eht rednu tlep kciht eht swohs
,rrup a tsomla ,lworg wol A
,stsurht dna shtaerb
.revo semit lareves tneps dna derit dna eros m’I
.yrt t’nod I
.em no flesmih selapmi ylwols
tsehc ym ,stipmra sih rednu parw smra yM
,skcab rieht no sedir dna sredluohs rieht no secnuop ti
.dnuorg eht ot sllaf
.niaga skaerc rood ehT
.etats detacixotni sih etipsed
.tnasaelp erom eb dluow sevac dna sgnirps toH
.trohS eht nipeP gniK htiw ekiL
,meht fo eno htiw gniklat emit hcum siht gnidneps ot desu ton m’I ”…I“
”…rebmemer I ekil tsuj er’uoY“
,edirP yppaH  .stsacdop ruoy
,enog si rehtaf ym dna ,nworg ma I
,raw sraey ythgie eht ni
.tsael ta ,nac sdnah neknurd sih sa hcum sa
,kcab nrut teef gnilbmutS
,daeh ym ssorca sevom dnah siH
,enim tsniaga mraw si ydob dekan sih ”,dnaloR ,wonk uoY“
,nwot siht gniklats retsnom emosdnah a fo srepsihw raeh ll’uoy
;eugnot ym no llits mih fo etsat rettib ehT
?ysae os neeb s’ti yhw taht sI
.sgnirps toh eht hguorht lleh morf pu delwarc taht lavemirp gnihtemos
”,sdnats thgin eno ym fo tsom htiW“ ?emit tsrif ehT
.skeehc sih neewteb gnitser em sleef eh nehw repmihw a sserppus t’nac eH
eno siht piks esaelp
,ylleb sih ,tsehc sih serolpxe eson yM
.maerd a morf flesmih ekaw ll’eh deirrow s’eh ekil ,evitatnet si repsihw s’nam ehT
nac uoY .éfac eht fo renroc yzoc eht ni ,gnafecI yb uoy rof daer
.ekil saw nehcaA fo vuakhaB dedaerD eht tahw raeh ot detnaw ohw wollef a morf
,tuo elbmuts gnihtolc delevehsid ni nem ruoF
.niks sih hsurb hteet ym nehw sredduhs eh dna
.retsnom a m’I   floWcaM boR dna
.tuons dna srae ym gnicart
.peels ot kcab tfird I sa elims I
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.thgin eht otni tuo cisum ecnad fo tsrub a gnisaeler
”,llew ,uoy dessim yeht fi dnA“
,ylleb sih no stser daeh ym
.doolb sih sknird dna
.sehctulc ym otni flesmih tup ot regae erom dnoces yreve s’eh dna
,nem ehT  ?retsnom eht teeM
.pleh ot sekil tsuj ohw
.eltrats ym sserppus ot evah I
”.uoy rof gnikool raf os emoc
”xiA fo tsaeB eht ot sweN dooG eht thguorB yehT woH“yojne esaelP
.yltneconni stser tah eht erehW
”.noitatuper a tog ev’uoy tuB“ .selkcuhc eH
,dnegel ot gnidrocca ,vuakhaB ehT .ecnuop I
gninaom mih fo dnuos eht
,meht no sesuohhtab rieht tliub snamoR eht erofeB
”?eman ruoy s’tahW“
.daor eht ssorca rood eht no dexif seyE
.vuakhab lufdaerd eht
.nwod daeh ym yal dna
.éfac eht fo renroc yzoc eht ni
,ecaf ym ot evom htob sdnah siH .apdnarg ekiL
.kcab sih otno mih llor I
.meht syals ti erofeb skcab rieht no ti yrrac ot meht secrof dna
.em ekil retsnom a ot troffe hcum ton llits tuB
.tah eht pu kcip sregnif gnilbmuF
,sreidlos hsinapS fo ynapmoc a yb
seye sih ni raef ehT .spil ym sepacse
,ksa ot hguone wonk uoy fI
.edis reivaeh eht no s’eH
,ynam oot pord eno eht si rewsna siH
,won terces nepo na s’tI
”.flesym elbatrofmoc meht ekam ot tseb ym did I“
.noitaraperp ni erab swalc dna sgnaf ;pu krep srae yM
,sraw dlrow htob fo sthgin detnecs-redwopnug eht delworp ohw
.gnirolpxe peek dna
.thgir dna tfel spihw liat gnol a ,wodahs eht nI
,eromyna vuakhab a tsuj ton m’I dna
.mih rebmemer od I won dnA …siH .eugnot sih
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.ekirts I nehw ,tsaf yrev m’I .gnitiaW
.tuo selbmuts nam rehtonA
.hguone esolc selbmuts eh nehw
?meht fo eno saw I ekiL
.ysatsce dna noitarebil fo thgin elgnis a rof egnahcxe ni
,tneps naht erom enim dna noissap sih ,retal emit emoS
,redluohs ym revo mih evaeh I
.krad s’ti tuB .mraW .yrd s’tI
,em revo sehsaw thgilteerts eht taht hguone tsuJ
.dehtaehs ylluferac swalc ym peek dna mih dnuora wap taht parw I os
”,ohw wonk ot ekil d’I kniht I“ .rewsna I
.gniknird neeb d’yeht mohw htiw yranecrem hsimelF a yawa deggard dna no decnuop ehs nehw
.detsugsid eb dluow srotsecna yM
redic drah dna ,akdov ,mur—
.ruf erab ym no tser secaf dna sdnah riehT
.mih ruoved ot desoppus m’I woh t’nsi sihT
.seye dettils fo kcab eht morf detcelfer thgil ehT .liat deggaj ehT
,rehtael dna ekoms fo setsat eH
,selcsum ym revocsid
.tnaw I tahw s’taht dna
.htuom ym ni egnarts leef sdrow ehT
seirraH nomoloS yb
.enod evah dluow rehtaf ym sa od t’nod I
,oga sraey emos si tI .rebmemer I dnA
,flesym evah I sa regnuh hcum sa htiw kcab sesserp eh tuB
nethgit sllab gnignah ym sa elgnit eht leef nac I
.thginot knard eh gnihtyreve etsat nac I taews sih ni dna ,taews fo setsat eh
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
…ot desoppus ylno m’I ,naem I ,ylno I“
,won ,tsehc ym no ruf eht gnikorts s’eh
gnidnopser fo noitidart deronoh-emit eht ni gniwollof ,seirraH nomoloS yb
.deen lamirp siH .enilanerda siH
.ssenkrad eht hguorht nwod mih gniyrrac
.dneb dna hcterts srednepsuS
.doolb sih knird dna
,niks tuat dna taews neknurd sih fo etsat eht
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,oga sraey derdnuh neves ,gnihtemos-dnarg taerg taerg yM
.ti nihtiw tcaf ni tub
,ssenkrad eht ot snrut daeh dlaB
si yrots s’yadoT
,kcen sih elbbin dna kcil I
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif
.rehtie em ot kcab emoc ot tnaw dluow meht fo eno taht aedi eht ot desu ton m’I tub
;thgin ta ,nem neknurd sklats tI
.em erofeb srotsecna ym ekil ,steerts eht klats I won dnA
.pilc rednepsus a esaeler sregnif sih sa ecnelis eht stuc pans A
.sih dnif spil ym daetsnI
,htuom sih fo etsat eht ot gninosaes tsuj era esoht tub—
tleb ym nepo elbmuf ot hguone gnol tsuj ydob ym evael sdnah siH
.sretsnom dna staerht erew ew
.doolb rieht sknird dna hself rieht sruoved neht dna
.taht ot yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I ”.sraey eseht lla
,yas ot desu yeht ,eraweB
,syas yrots eht os
?ssergorp emos edam evah yeht t’ndluohs neht
.kcen ym fo kcab eht sbur eH
.nem nezod a flah yb dednuorrus ,yal I
,resolc mih llup ot eslupmi eht thgif t’nac I
…tnaw ylniatrec yeht
.niaga em ssik ot ni em slluP
.seog yerp eht erehw og ew tuB
.hcum klat t’nod I
.sevorpmi yteicos dna
elbiduani yllacitcarp si tekcaj rehtael ym fo elffuhs ehT
.noitanimoba na em llac dluow yeht
.sllaw etercnoc eht gnola gniohce srrup dna slworg dna sdog-ho dna snaom
~~ .yrt lliw I ,spahrep ,kniht I
.llet ot drah s’ti
,sdap ym tsniaga ,detaeh dna digir
.srotsecna ym tsugsid os dluow tahw s’tI
.raef ot desoppus era yeht retsnom ehT
.shgiht sih neewteb yaw sti skrow elzzum ym llit rewol dna
?em ot meht gnidnes neeb …eh saH
.traeh sih drawot sevom dnah ykahs siH
!vuakhab lufdaerd eht
~ .ti rof em knaht ot evil ll’eh dna ,yaw ym
.ehtaehsnu ot swalc naht retteb hcum gnihtemos tog ev’I tuB
,ruf tfos ym hguorht nur
.htaerb gnol a ward I
.esoppus I ,gnirudne fo yaw a evah sdnegeL
,sraey eht revo ,sknird wef a naht erom thguob neeb ev’I“  ?noitatupeR
,tah sih sexif eH .ylleb a fo tiB
.dneirf dlo na ekil em teerg sdnuos gnippird ehT
,sgnaf ym neewteb repeed sesserp eugnot siH
,nwot siht sklats retsnom suoedih A
.sesuohhtab dna seitrap eht ,sbulc eht ,srab eht fo sdnuor eht sekam taht lavemirp gnihtemos
.ehcatsum gnipoord gnol a dniheb raef neddus
,eb ot hcaer ym stcepxe eh tahw dnoyeB
,ti rednu sespalloc dna ,yas sdnegel eht
.yawa kcolb a renroc eht gninrut won puorg eht sa enut emas eht flesmih ot gnimmuH
.steerts eht ffo meht gnikat ,yteicos ot ecivres a gniod er’eW
ym dluoW .erom rof ytsriht meht sevael dna ,sdeb rieht otni sknils ti ;yad dna thgin
tsael ta“ ,no seog eh
,sredluohs s’nam knurd a ot no gnihctal yb kcatta sti snigeb
.em erofeb srotsecna ym ekil ton tuB
”?rettam ti seoD“ .srepsihw eh
.rotaderp A .gnitapicitna
.tniop eht si raeF
,mitciv a no sthgis ym tes I nehw oS
.ereht thgiR .sey hO
denrael eb nac tahw taht
.esle gnihtemos ot segnahc
.niaga mih tem I ecnis sthgin ynam woh ,won thgir ,rebmemer t’nod I neeb s’tI
tah ehT .yella eht tsap