nem era ohw sdneirf oT
,edirP ot rettam ytitnedi dna ytilauxes taht lla roF
,ma I ohw fo duorp ma I taht ylerem ton si tI
.daed tey ton er'ew roF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,sraeb era ohw sdneirf oT
,dekan ,dloh ot hsiw I mohW  sdneirf ynam ot smeoP
floWcaM boR yb meop a
.sessa rieht rof sreyarP
.stibbar yag elttil ehT tuoba kaeps taht smeoP
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
eno siht piks esaelp
noissap erew smaerd ym lla tuB
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,elzzum lufetarg ym tsniagA
.era ew ohw fo duorp era ew taht si ti
htnoM edirP s’raey tsal od-tuo ot ecnahc a was ohw ,floWcaM boR yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT
.yrellag yrruFoS sih
.smeop tuoba klat dnA
?I dna uoy ton fI
sexof ro sevlow osla dnA
,”uoY tuobA eB yaM yehT esehT gnidaeR erA uoY fI“
ssenkrad eht ni duol ehtaerB
no yrteop sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.dad regdab yldduc
.ruf tsehc s'dog ym fO
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,gnileef eht fo smeoP
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
em ediseb sdnabsuH
.sgod ekil evol ohw dnA
.dad regdab yldduc
ekots su ekil slamina tahT snoissap eht fo smeoP
,su gnitinu fo tseretni eht ni eroferehT
.sluos rieht ni ,snoil rO
,stibbar yag elttil ehT  rof yarp lliw ohw roF
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
.desuor oot ma I dnA
.dellacer-flah smeop dnA snoitcere-raen gniredloms oT denrut evah smaerd ym llA
”uoY tuobA eB yaM yehT esehT gnidaeR erA uoY fI“ saw sihT
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
,erom peels ot thguo I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf snoitcelloc ni krow sih dnif nac uoY .ti koot dna
,sregdab yrgnuh ekil thgif ohW
.esirnus erofeb tsuJ
:dnatsrednu esaelp
.su etinu yeht taht si
erom srettam tahw