,foohnorI mokÕaT yb daeR
.snoitalutargnoC !wow ,hOÒ
?I tÕnera ,dewercs mÕI
É ot txeN !eceip latem a É hu ,dnA .thgiR !yakO
,evird leehw-ruof dah elcihev sÕysiaD
.sesion gnihcleuqs ,kcilS
.niaga dekconk eH
,ediw tnew seye sÕociR
Ó.dab gnitteg era sdaor eht raeh I
Ó?taht uoy llet yllautca eh diDÒ
,tsuJ .mU .hOÒ .deksa ysiaD
.delggig oirt ehT
,deggurhs knumpihc ehT
ysiaD Ð !uoy etaicerppA
.potretnuoc eht ffo gnippoh ,derussa ylliT
.daeh reh detlit ehS
Ó?reteews sÕrevehcihw ,mUÒ
Ó.ymmuy erew yehT !sgnillif tun detrossAÒ .detcejni yaK
Ó.erus eb ot detnaw tsuJÒ Ó.puYÒ
,mih gnilddarts dna ,sgel ,shgiht reh gnidaerps
.edisni saw reveohw deduorhs sekalf gnilriws ,gnillaF
.htaerb a tuo welb knumpihc derae-gnol ehT .neeS
,detsisni eh Ó!ysub os neeB
.llew tnew
,dooh eht deppop knumpihc ehT
!raf os tÕnsaHÒ
ÕsgnikcotsÔ rebbur sa llew sa ,no tekcaj retniw a gnittup
.nirg dehtootkcub A
.daeha pu saw eciffo siH
.snoitibihni sih gniwaht noitisopsid ynnus reh
Ó.gnurts-hgih os mÕIÒ
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
!sklof ,niaga Õrehtaew kcosliatÔ gathsah sÕtIÒ
.ylyrd dias eh Ó?lla taht sIÒ
Ó.em tsurT !ti evol llÕuoYÒ
.kaeps ot drah ti dnuof knumpihc ehT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.evom reh gnihctaw ,delggig ociR
.esucxe laer a fo kniht ot elbanu
.ti revo lla eugnot sih gnicnad ,elppin a no delkcus ociR
,tnemom a rof mih pota gniyaL
.ydob sih gnihcra ,deffuh ociR
.ydob sih pu trihs sih deggut ylregae ,steknalb eht htaeneb gnihtirw ,arabypac ehT .ria dloc eht otni dna steehs eht fo tuo ,daeh sih evoba smra sih gnisiar yb derewsna ociR Ó?em nioJÒ
Ó.hsittiks oS !yug rooPÒ
,daetsni spih yvruc
.hsulb ot gnitrats ,deksa ydnaM
Ó,ereh erÕuoy dalg os mÕIÒ
Ó.esuoh a dah uoy wonk tÕndid IÒ
,yhself sih htiw radar eht ta detniop eH
É ot oG ratS dna braBÒ   .ti thguac eH
.yteixna sih fo tcudorpyb a ,deggar saw htaerb siH Ó.krad dnA .dloc yllaer sÕti dna ,moorhtab eht esu ot pu ekow I
,deeps lluf ta gnihsiws erew srepiw dleihsdniw ehT ).did eH(
Ó,tuo tnew rewop ehTÒ
Ó?yako gnihtyrevEÒ .gniyrc neeb dÕeh taht edih ot gniyrt
Ó.citauqa-imes era eWÒ
.sdrow sih tsol eh tub
,dedda ylkciuq dna desuap knumpihc ehT
.dnoces a tsuj rof ezorf eH .dekan sÕehS
!31 lennahC ta gniteem a daH
,renroc a denrut ociR nehw dedaf sdnuos ehT
slirtson ytevlev ,egral reH
Ó!mMÒ .noitatiseh tuohtiw dias ociR Ó,kerTÒ
,tuoba detsiwt ociR
,srae ekil-poocs ,rednels sih htiW
.retniw on ,drazzilb on ,dlrow on saw erehT
,dloc a saw tI  esuoM .T dleiF yb
Ó É yakOÒ .mih dlot ehs
ÓÉ haey ,ha É hAÒ .tnew eh
Ó.uoy tnaw I !ti tnaw IÒ
Ó?moordeb eraps a sah ti dnAÒ
.teehsdeb a ni depparw moordeb eht fo tuo deklaw ociR ,gninrom txen ehT
.delims ociR Ó?thgiRÒ
.mih nevig dÕehs dihcro eht ekil tsomla
.eert gnorw eht pu gnirepmacs mÕI .rehtegoT
.sesuoh eht ta wons eht hguorht detniuqs dna wodniw eht ot eson sih desserp ociR
.daeha pu der denrut thgil a sa ekarb ot detrats arabypac ehT Ó.meht setaicerppa ffats elohw eht erus mÕIÒ Ó!dooGÒ
,gnillaf wons ees dluoc eh
.ysub tog tub ylper ot tnaeM .yrros ,haeYÒ
,esuoM .T dleiF yb
.swap sih ni ecaf sih deirub dna ,thgil eht no denrut
,dehtaerb eh ,gnilffinS
Ó?yas tÕnod uoYÒ Ó.oot ,eMÒ
.eliforp lluf ni ydob ,pu doots ysiaD
Ó.haey ,tuB .gnihtyna ro noisnam a ekil toN .yrots-elgniSÒ
,nups serit raer ehT
?esuoh ym ta moor eraps a evah IÒ
,nworb-hsidder yltsom saw tlep sÕociR ,erutats ni etiteP
Ó.mmh-mMÒ Ó.oot ,uoy ot thgindooGÒ
,thgin eht fo elddim eht saw tI
Ó!?morf yeht era ohWÒ
.xaler ot nageb ociR
Ó!rrB .retniW .rM Õlo fo spirg yci eht ni peed erÕew esuac
.gnol tsal tÕndid tahT
.ytic eht fo retnec cihpargoeg eht saw elcriC ehT
.seidob tneps rieht revo kcab steknalb dna steehs eht lla dellup neht ehS .decnuob deb ehT
dehsaw arabypac eht elihW Ó!eciohc dooGÒ
?fo diarfa os I ma tahW
,redluohs reh dnuof elzzum reitniop siH
.ni tog eh nehw gnirevihs neeb dÕeH
.niaga deirt dna sdnoces wef a detiaw knumpihc ehT
.rebmun reh dah eH
.moor eht otni gnirutnev
.degnahc dah gnihtyrevE
.raey tsal sa emaS
.pu gnikool ,demialcxe ehs
Ó.uoy tsurt I esuaceBÒ
ÓÑot stnaw yllatot ecnanetniam ni llub tahT .suoivbo sÕtIÒ
.derettum ociR Ó,neetrihTÒ
.riahc a revo gnippirt ylraen dna kcab gnippets
.rewolf yna naht lufituaeb erom sÕehS
,seye neerg kcormahs sih ta debbur eH
?spil dloc ro ssenyhs gnilppirC
Ó!pop-maerd emos em evoL !seYÒ
Ó.oot ,tahTÒ .dekoj ysiaD
Ó?taht egnahc tÕnac uoy ekil dnuos ti ekam uoYÒ .gnidnatsrednu
,seerged 0 dnuora eb lliw thginot swol lautcAÒ
.fo draeh reven dah eh puorg a no delttes eh
?snoollab htiw od I dluow tahW
.og teehs eht tel ociR
Ó.mmh-mMÒ Ó?siht denigami evÕuoy É uoYÒ
Ó?Õlooc ylsseltroffeÔ ni sAÒ
.wohemos ,etamitni erom siht edam ssenkrad ehT
,stnedor lla fo tseggib eht erew sarabypaC .hsulp dnA
Ó.tuo dab llitS .enin retfAÒ
Ó.gnidir rof srabeldnah ni-tliub tog evÕyeht ,haeYÒ
?mmh ,tsafkaerb erofeb evoLÒ
.dalas dna atsap fo slwob nwod gnicalp
Ó.doohrobhgien ecin a si sihTÒ
,gnidiced yletamitlu
Ó.semalf eht esuod nac ohw eno ylno eht erÕuoy dna
.daor eht no erew yeht
.detrats cisum eht dna
Ó.deb eht rednu yrTÒ
Ó!era uoy ereht ,hOÒ    Ó É mUÒ
Ó.sterces evah ot hguone gnitseretni ton mÕIÒ
tsuj IÒ Ó.tsrif uoYÒ
.ot deirt :noitcerroC
.dednefed ydnaM Ó,yksirf mÕI
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
ÓtsafkaerB erofeB evoLÒ
,denaom ysiaD Ó!ysiaDÒ
.ti hguorht gniklaw dna rood eht gninepo ,deddon ociR
Ó.si moorhtab eht erehw wonk ydaerla uoYÒ .dereffo ehs
.sesor fo teuquob hserf eht dellems ehs sa deralf
Ó.taht ekil eb dluoc I hsiw yllaeRÒ
Ó!seY .tuo sniarb reHÒ Ó?yllaeRÒ
.mraw gnitteg skeehc
Ó,elbuort rac emos gnivaH !wonkÕy
.denrut dnA .denruT
.delkcuhc ehS Ó?ffatSÒ
.resolc dekool knumpihc ehT ?rewolf dettop A
,rood eht denepo ociR
.tnedor a morf draeh reve dÕeh sa rrup a ot esolc sa saw tI
.sredluohs reh dnuora epac a ekil steknalb dna steehs eht gniraew
.elpoep rehto rof krow gninedrag tnatropmi siht lla od I
Ó.retaw ekil uoy ffo llor tsuj sgniht ,on ,tuBÒ
,)nuf yllis ,tsenrae ;ti deyojne dah ociR(
.redrah neve mih edam sihT
.looc reh esol ro cinap reh nees reven dÕeH
.gniht a sÕereht ,hO
.tiurf a sdeeN .mmHÒ
.noitats oidar silopanaidnI na ta dekrow knumpihc ehT
Ó.naem I ,tuo uoy gnittup ton mÕI tahTÒ
Ó!tnih a su eviGÒ .knis eht yb potretnuoc eht no gnittis yllausac saw ehS
?sraW ratS ro kerT ratSÒ
Ñdezilaer ylneddus eh dna
,htob meht revo sgnirevoc eht dellup ysiaD .leef ot rehtonA
,gnirps emoCÒ .dias ehs
.potpal reh ta gnikool elihw maj htiw tsaot gnitae ,nehctik eht ni ysiaD dnuof eh
,erus tÕnera uoy fIÒ
.rood eciffo sih denepo ociR
,dehgis eH .gnihton llitS
Ó.uoy pleh ot enoemos deen uoy ebyaMÒ Ó.deirt evÕIÒ
.reh fo dehtaerb eh dna
.tekcop sih fo tuo enohp sih dellup knumpihc ehT Ó É hsiw IÒ
ÓÑym ot kcab og tsuj llÕI É yllis gnieb mÕIÒ
.erutseg sselpleh A
.emoh nwo ym fo ycavirp eht ni mÕIÒ Ó É gnihtoN
tÕnoDÒ .tsacerof yad-7 eht gniwohs
Ó!esaelp ,esaelp ,esaelPÒ
.edis htron eht no erew yeht ,yltnerruC
.tsul htiw gnippird eciov
!dihcro na naht retteb hcum sÕrewolf reH .hsog ,hO
.ylf eht no seiromem sih gnicrofnier
,mih ta gnilims tsuJ
.etihw-ffo yklim a edistnorf sih gnivael ,ydob sih nwod dna kcab tnew dna
?ffo dezod I retfa tsuj tuo enog evÕtsum É evÕtsuMÒ .denialpxe ociR
Ó?yaD sÕenitnelaV rof teg uoy did tahWÒ
.liat sih gnidloh knumpihc eht deciton ehs
.reh ot esolc os saw eh tub
skeehc sih no detrats nrettap lacirtemmys ehT
,elbat eht dnuora gniyahsas
Ó É taht ekil dednuos sarabypac wonk tÕndid É tÕndid IÒ
?eno ylno eht saw I É oS Ó.hOÒ
.secalp tseb eht lla ni ,ydob elohw siH
.steehs eht htaeneb ylluf gnilggirw erofeb ti desserac dna deporg eh
Ó.lliw I ,tÕnod uoy fI !mih htiw teG
,gnikahs ,arabypac eht degguh eH
É srobhgien dna sdneirf esoht no kcehc ot erus eb dna ,hOÒ
.detsisni ehs Ó!ni emoCÒ
,spag eht ni dellif dnim siH
,slatep reh neewteb ti gnitcerid ,rebmem sih mia ot wap a htiw nwod dehcaer knumpihc ehT
.oNÒ Ó?gnorw gnihtemoSÒ
.deksa ehs Ó?retteBÒ .mih ecaf ot edis reh no gnillor
,egral reh denael ysiaD
,niaga degnahc pam ehT
Ó?taht tuoba erus uoYÒ
.htmraw dna ytefas fo elbbub sseldne na tsuJ
.denrut enigne ehT
?ta gnikool I ma tahW   .delffins eH
Ó É tub ,yllaer toN ?eM ?sraCÒ Ó?ociRÒ
Ó?em ot emoc dluow gnihtemos ebyam ,dooh eht deppop I fi derugif IÒ
.ylhsipeehs derettihc eH Ó.yakO !hOÒ
.tah naggobot sih fo edis rehtie no lluks sih ot esolc gninnip srae gnol
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,elihw eht lla daeh sih fo kcab eht deldarc swap reH
.gnol eb tÕndluow ti wenk eh
.kaerb fo tuo dna ni meht gnignirb ,sllac gnirrefsnart dna gnineercs
.llah tnecajda eht otni
Ó.dnekeew siht wohs on sÕerehT
Ó,etam ym morf setalocohc tog I ,elihwnaeMÒ Ó.tÕndluow uoYÒ
.dehctiwt sreksihw siH ?ebut A
.erutan ni gnihtyna sa lufrewop sa ,tlob gninthgil a ekil
.regnorts gnitteg erew stsug dniW .dnuora gnippihw
.xes neklis ,mraw reh tsniaga gnibbur noitcere sih ,deffuh ociR
Ó.gig oidar eht sllik taht sseuGÒ
,retal setunim eviF       Ó.ociR ,ni teGÒ
.wolley dna ,knip ,deR
.dleihsdniw eht no egassem lanif ym tuo evrac nac I
,kcab sih debbur swap debbew sÕysiaD
Ó?yas ot gniog uoy erew tahw É hu
Ó,nettog reve evÕI tfig sÕenitnelaV tseb eht saw thgin tsal ,wonk uoYÒ
.em fo esuaceb tew sÕehS
,pit-elzzum reh no
,meht neewteb derednaw wap siH
.deksa ehs Ó?tey gnihtyna dniFÒ
.gnilgnit flesmih tlef knumpihc ehT
?yawllah eht ni gniod siht sÕtahW !? É eht tahW
,mubla na pu dekcip eH Ó.eurTÒ
!lleWÒ ,dias dna deppots arabypac eht
,rehtaew tnemelcni eht ot euD
.keehc sih tsniaga gnihsup eson tnulb
,retal ruoh-na-flaH
.seye sih ta gnibbur ,duola deksa eh
,smsaps ralucsum ,lufrewop yb dekcarw ,delppir xes reH
Ó,fnhUÒ .mih nopu nwod thgiew reh deppord ysiaD
.kcab gniog on saw erehT
Ó É ociRÒ ,derepsihw ysiaD
.reh no hsurc a dah eh ,osla ,dnA
.regnif a desiar ehS
,delbmuh ,knumpihc ehT
,erehwyna gniog tÕnsaw eh fi tub
pu evig ot tuoba saw knumpihc ehT
,reh rof Õdraob eht narÔ ociR
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.reh ot dekool eH
.saw ti dloc woh gniredisnoc taef a saw hcihw ,dehsulb ociR
,sruof lla ot flesreh gnihsup dna ylleb reh otno gnillor ,tuoba detfihs ehS
,taob emas eht ni ,arabypac ehT
.tilc reh ta gnibbur ylsuoiruf ,noinu rieht fo ecruos eht ot tnew rehto ehT
,ylliT gnirutaef tsefbag yliad a
Ó!hu É Ò É dna niaga pu esor neht dna
.liat yhsub sih fo dloh gnibbarg
.ecnesse yrev sih rof mih gniklim
,gnitsisni ,delims ociR
.tsal eht naht tnetop dna lufyalp erom saw ssik hcaE Ó É mm É erÕuoy fi
.lerriuqs yerg a ,yaK dedaelp
.taht pota gnitser saw mih nevig dÕehs dihcro eht dna
.hctiwt mih gnileef
Ó.elbat nehctik ym pu nevil llÕtIÒ .delims eH Ó.haeYÒ
.sdrocer hguorht kool ot gniunitnoc ,delims ociR
.ti hguorht gnikeep
Ó!ti esu ot emoclew erÕuoY
,pal sih no saw gab potpal sÕociR
Ó?srac gnixif tuoba gnihtyna wonk uoy oD .huHÒ
!ebyaM .wonk tÕnod I É mu
.nosaes gniworg eht gnirud
.ecarbme eht tsiser tÕndid ociR
,deddon ,dehsulb ociR Ó.pu yrruH .nIÒ
.mraw ehs saw ,hsog ,hO
Ó,dehsinif tuoba tsuj erÕeWÒ
.remrahC eniuqE eht
.lin yllacitcarp saw ytilibisiv tub
!ereh llits erÕew yhw sÕtahTÒ .dezigolopa yaK
?meht dnes tÕndid eh fi tahw ,yawynA
meht rof serutaef gninrom gnirrucer gniod tuoba recudorp sih ot klat I detseggus eHÒ ,deunitnoc ysiaD
,tfahs eht dnuora gnilruc sregnif
.tuo yaw ym no mÕIÒ
.rennid elpmis a gniraperp saw ysiaD
.tol gnikrap siht ni eid ot gniog ylbaborP
.enod sÕehs wohs yreve ot denetsil evÕI !dihcro nA
.detrad seye neerg sÕociR
Ó.snottub thgir eht sserp ot gnilliWÒ
,dias dna flesmih riahc eht devom ociR
,deremmats eH .desserp ehs
,teews dna peeD .ssik A
Ó.gnileef erÕuoy tahw ot evom É tsuj uoY
Ó?selbac evah uoy oD ?ti gnipmuj deirt uoy evaH
,esuoM .T dleiF yb ÓtsafkaerB erofeB evoLÒ saw sihT
,tah dna taoc sih no tup eh sA .yaK dna ,ydnaM
,gnirettahc hteeT Ó.tnaw
.nedrag kcab dna tnorf a evah ot gniog mÕI
Ó É gninrom siht mih dehctaw IÒ Ó.eno eht sÕtahTÒ
.rood moordeb sÕysiaD no gnikconk ,sfeirb-rexob dna trihs-t a ni
.egde sti no nwod eldeen eht tes yltneg dna
Ó.Õrerimda terceSÔ !haHÒ
,selppa eht fo eno decils dna
.aera gniweiv 31 lennahC eht ni era uoy erehw no gnidneped
.edom tluafed reh fo traP
Ó,hcnul rof ytrap yadiloh a dah ew ,yrroSÒ
.ropav nwerts-dniw sa dnuora gnippihw htaerb ,delahxe ociR Ó É oNÒ
.delggig slrig ehT
Ó.yffulf dna etuc oSÒ
erehTÒ .sevlehs aidem reh ot revo deddap ,gnidnats llits ,arabypac ehT .skeehc yhcterts sih gnibbur
,deggeb arabypac eht Ó!em ot ti eviGÒ Ó!annog mÕI
,tahWÒ Ó.melborp oNÒ
.ti kaerb ot tnaw tÕndid dna oga skeew wef a ti teS
É mMÒ .niaga mih gnissik ,desimorp ehs
Ó.ruf eht ni gnieb ,elbatrofmoc os sÕtIÒ
.noitautis eht gnillabwol ,deilper eh
,raewrednu sih otni sbmuht reh dekooh ysiaD
.degnahc mih dniheb pam eht sa edisa deppets esuom derruf-nedlog ehT
.ti gnitfil dna rac eht fo tuo gnilggirw
.moor eraps eht ot knumpihc eht dewohs ysiaD
.edisa dellor daeh siH Ó?hOÒ
,rood eht desolc ociR
,neerg denrut thgil ehT
Ó!noos tuo denori gnihtemos teg llÕew kniht I
,hcuoc eht no tas eH
Ó É taht od tÕnac I !tÕnac IÒ
.kcab ti tup neht dna ,revoc kcab eht ta dekool
,wollip sih no kcab daeh
.syawla sa llihc dna mlac ,deksa arabypac eht Ó?gnorw sÕtahWÒ
.wollem ,teewS
.elbat eht ot doof gnirrefsnart nageb ysiaD Ó.gnihtynAÒ
.taorht sih deraelc eH Ó.sknahT .thgiR .hOÒ
Ó.erahs ot taeh ydob fo ytnelp tog evÕIÒ
.moor gnivil eht ni pu dnuow yeht ,rennid retfA
.stiurf depahs-ebolg ,der owt pu pleh dna egdirf reh denepo ehS
,siht dias ehs sA
,meht neewteb kcab wap a gnignirB
.liat sih debmoc eH
.cigol sÕetam sih tluaf tÕndluoc eH
,elprup-hsiulb diviv a erew seye reH .swap dna ,srae
ÓÑI ,lleWÒ .deddon ysiaD Ó.yakOÒ
.detsal dah taht gnol woh
ÓÑtuB !uoy ekaw ot yrros yllaer mÕI ,kool É mÕI ,mUÒ
.esnopser a rof gninetsil
,ni nioj ot ydaer tÕnsaw eh gnieeS
Ó,ociR ,artnam a ekil taht gnitaert potSÒ
.reyalp csid eht pu gnittes ,VT eht no denrut ysiaD
sehcni 8 ot 4 sa hcum sa eb dluoc noitalumuccAÒ .liat elisneherp
Ó,sseug lla nac ew erus mÕIÒ Ó É hoOÒ
Ó.ereh tuo ezeerf uoy tel ot gniog ton mÕIÒ
.gnihtyna meht evig tÕndid IÒ
.leehw gnireets eht no sregnif reh demmurd arabypac ehT Ó.hOÒ .rehtaew doog nI .yaw enO
!derettihc ociR .spalS
,niaga drawrof devom yeht dna neerg denrut thgil ehT Ó.enif erÕuoYÒ
Ó?sehtolc ym dnif tÕndluoc I É I ,oSÒ .desuap eH
?snoitarbiv esohT ?gnirruhc tahT
Ó.rehtie ,seno doog yna evah tÕnod IÒ
,daeh sih gnignah
.liat yriah reh dekcilf ehS
.heHÒ Ó.thgil ytterp si ot netsil I cisum eht fo tsoMÒ
,gib reh dehsiws ysiaD os
,oot Õ,nosaes nettim raeÔ gathsah ni worhT
Ó?yawyna dnuora gnivird uoy erew yhw É hu ,yhWÒ
.sredluohs sih gnigassam ,kcen sih gnibbur
Ó?od ot gniog I ma tahWÒ
.tnemtrapa sih ot etummoc etunim-53 a saw tI
seltit eht fo emos gnidaer ,dias ociR
Ó,citoxiuq era sknumpihCÒ
?siht riaper ot ereh teg ylbissop dluow ohw
.ksed sih no gnihtemos deciton ociR
,sgninepo em gnivig speek ehS ?serac ohW
?kaeps ,nosaer ,kniht ot ytiliba ehT
.taes sih ni digir gniog ydob
Ó.kcab yaw ym no yllanif mÕI
Ó.esnes htxis a evah eWÒ
.lezah thgil dna eeffoc krad fo sepirts gnitanretla yb detpurretni
,derevihs ociR .MA 2 saw tI
Ó,tibbaR retniW eht dna aciremA nat-ypaCÒ
,resolc deppets eh
.krad eht otni ti gnissot
.erehwyna gniog toN
.sretcarahc rettirc fo royevrup a
,knumpihc derae-gnol a ,ociR
.yawa setunim net evil ylno I
.llah rehtona otni srood fo tes a hguorht gnissap
.mih ta deddon ysiaD
?taht ekil eb I tÕnac yhW
.dezisatnaf eh ,semitemoS
.revo lla hcum ytterp
,kcoc sih debbarg dna sgel sih neewteb dehcaer ehs
.wodniw regnessap eht tuo dekool
.tuo gninethgiarts erofeb dnoces a rof gniliathsif rac eht
.gnihcni oN .gnisaet oN
Ó.oot ,uoy evol I .uoy tog evÕIÒ
.yrots nigiro na sdeen pihs-etam yreve ,orehrepus a ekiL !lleWÒ
.tsrif-ecaf nwod deppolf dna
.ni knis taht tel arabypac ehT Ó.yrots
,recudorp sÕwohs eht sA
tceffe ni si gninraW mrotS retniW A
,derumrum ysiaD Ó,oot ,uoy tnaw IÒ
.ytilanosrep doog a hcus sah ehS
.won ,sraey elpuoc a ereh neeb dÕeH
.esirprus etelpmoc a tÕnsaw taht os
É tub ,meht tsniaga gnihton ,naem I
.deksa ysiaD Ó?meÔ neeSÒ
,wodniw eht tuo gnikooL
.stsaerb reh htiw level-eye syawla saw eh
Õ.ruoH rewolF sÕysiaDÔ
.ot klaw ot yawa raf oot si pots sub tseraeN
?reh txet dluohs I ebyaM
.yldwel gnippolf stsaerb ,nwod dna pu gnicnuob ,thgirtuo mih edor ysiaD
,sdrocer eht ot kcaB Ó.ebyaMÒ
.esion gnirruhc tcnitsid a edam ysiaD Ó!hAÒ
Ó.ti ees yllautca tÕndid uoy os
!wohs ym fo rats eht gnieb rof sknahT
Ó?ykriuq naem uoy tÕnoD ?citoxiuQÒ
.yaw sih deklaw ehs sa enot gnosgnis a ni dias ysiaD Ó,ociR ,hOÒ
Ó.dnert gnimraw etaredom a htiw keew txen fo elddim ti fo tuo llup llÕeW !epoh esol
.niaga kcab neht dna rehto eht ot eno morf dehctiws eH
.detseggus ehs Ó,ociR ,lyniv a no tuPÒ
Ó.taht od ot evah tÕnod uoy
.egassap reh ta thgir
Ó.thgiRÒ Ó.ytud pu naelC
.yaw gnorw eht gnicaf selcihev ,sredneb redneF .stnedicca ronim wef a dessap yehT
.ti delrufnu knumpihc ehT
.ylippah denoitnem ehs
.dihcro na em evag ehS
Ó.citoxiuq ,oNÒ .deksa ydnaM
,dias ehs Ó,I od rehtieNÒ
elbatnrut eht no csid deroloc-neerg eht tup eH .amuoZ imuY
Ó,hcum yrev ,sey ,ha É hAÒ Ó?detseretnIÒ
,naem I É rof lufetarg mÕIÒ
.rehtie ,seye reh gnisolc tÕnsaw ysiaD
.rac sih detrats ociR
!taht fo drocer lyniv a tnaw I
,sliat evah tÕndid sarabypaC
.yllairotaripsnoc denraw yaK
.tnemssarrabme htiw dehgual eH Ó?huHÒ .desaet ehs
.rewolf eht fo ,deksa ysiaD
.llew snoitidnoc eht gnildnah saw ti os
Ó!no kcab sÕrewoPÒ ÓÑtÕnod I ebyam tuBÒ
Ó.hguoht ,elcriC eht fo htuos evil I É hu ,IÒ
,tuo llits saw rewop ehT
?gnirats mih hctac tÕndid ehs depoh eH
dnuof eb nac krow siH
Ó.emoh uoy ekat llÕI ,edir a deen uoy fIÒ
.gnimaerd eb ton retteb I
Ó?rood ym ot emoc uoy did yhw
.esuoh sÕysiaD ta devirra yeht ,hguone nooS Ó É haeYÒ
.derit fo etisoppo eht ylneddus saw eh tub
Ó,denigami I naht retfos neve erÕuoYÒ
,relevart wollef ruoy
.etunim a rof deldduc yehT Ó É oot ,eMÒ
xes reh ot guns sllab yzzuf
Ó?yalp I dluohs tahw É hu ,tahWÒ
!dab os erÕuoy ,ylliTÒ .detrons ydnaM
Ó.psaW eht dna naM retaetnAÒ
si yrots sÕyadoT dna
.cidemoC .detraehthgil gnihtemos ebyaM
,elprup tnarbiv ,hciR .dihcro nA
.edis eht ot deb reh fo retnec eht morf gnitfihs
Ó,won ,revo sÕtahTÒ Ó.diarfa saw I
.sdneirf tseb erew yeht fi sa rac sih fo edis eht dettap eH
.noitalipmoc Õfo tsebÔ a ria dluow noitats eht
,kcalb tsomla ,rekrad tog roloc ehT
.no dekrow eh margorp etirovaf sih saw tI
.gnimmuh enigne ,mih ot txen pu dellup VUS na
.swalc reh detcepsni ylliT
,detnap ociR ,trapa dekcams
?thgir ,txet ym tog uoYÒ
Ó.mmh-mMÒ .noitcere sih fo ,dias ehs Ó?em roFÒ
.dekan mih teg arabypac eht gnipleh
,stsaerb lufituaeb
.rood nepo eht fo emarf eht tsniaga emarf derruf-nworb
,tsaerb a gnidnif
.yawa gnikool ,dehsulb ociR
!yawllah ruoy ot dereviled gnieb snoollab was IÒ .mih deksa ydnaM
.moor nwo reh ot tnew dna kcab deppets yllanif arabypac eht ,tnemom a rof gniregniL
.flehs yaR-ulB sÕysiaD morf
.em ot detcartta ton sÕehS
.noitseuq a tÕnsaw tI
swap htob htiw ti deldarc eH
.remrahC eniuqE eht
.deppir sÕeh ,lriGÒ
.moc.yrrufos.lerriuqs ta
.dliw ociR evord taht esion lacisum ,gnillirt a edam ysiaD
Ó.samtsirhC rof meht tog I radnelac Õyad eht fo drowÔ taht gnisu sÕenoemoSÒ ,denoitnem ylliT
,enihcam eht dehcaorppa ociR Ó.yakOÒ
Ó!em ot Õkrow rof efasÔ dnuos tÕnseod sgnillif tuNÒ Ó.owt uoy ekilnU .Õkrow rof efasÔ noitasrevnoc siht peek ot gniyrt mÕI tub ,oNÒ Ó?lla taht sIÒ
.sih ot spih reh gnidnirg detrats ehs ,emit on gnitsaW
Ó?ton yhWÒ Ó É taht od tÕnac IÒ
Ó?em nioj ot gniog uoy tÕnerAÒ
.mih ediseb deppolf dna detnuomsid ysiaD
Ó!sepip ruoy tcetorp ot tegrof tÕnod dna
.sgniht ni tseb eht gnidniF .gniogysae ,mraW
É mÕIÒ Ó!hho É hOÒ
.yltneitap dias ysiaD Ó,ociRÒ
É tnew eh sa noitasrevnoc rieht raeh llits dluoc eh
spih esoht deimmihs ehs sa
,foohnorI mokÕaT yb daeR daer
Ó!?esuoM gninroM eht biF .tiaW .hOÒ
,derrucnoc ydnaM Ó,haeYÒ
!og tÕndluow tI Ó É no emoc ,no emoCÒ
?pihsnoitaler ecalpkrow ruo gnignahC
.recudorp a sa Õsenecs eht dnihebÔ yltsoM
.ti llems ,ti leef dluoc eH .tew saw ehS
.llihc eht deciton yldrah yehT
,aremac eht ta elims dehtootkcub ,gib a dehsalf eH
.senotrednu knip ,mraw htiw eulb no gniredrob
,dias ociR ,tnemom a retfA
.deriaper eb neve dluoc ti fI
.htuom sih denepo eh ,ysiaD ot kcab gnikooL
,dias eh Ó,melborp oNÒ Ó!ociR ,sknahTÒ
.yllacinhcet ,yaD sÕenitnelaV tÕnsaw tIÒ
,reh naht retrohs toof a gnieB .moxuB .yvruC
.ti ediseb sdrocer fo xob a hguorht gnippilf
.htaerb peed a koot ociR Ó É
?yaD sÕenitnelaV rof nettog eh dah tahW
nworb yhtrae ,ytsaot a saw ruf reH
.tlep sih otni sehtolc sih tsap gid dloc eht leef ot gnitrats ,gnirevihs
?won ,seye ym esolc I dluohS
.deb eht gnittap dna srevoc eht kcab gniworht ,delims ehS
Ó.ecnad ot woh wonk tÕnod I !yaw oNÒ
.kcab daeh reh gnitlit ,denaom ehS
.noitpecxe on saw ehs dna
.dias ysiaD Ó,tsigoloroetem A
.erac tÕndid eh tuB
Ó?eno tnaW .selppa tog osla I
Ó.thgindoog a uoy hsiw ot gniog saw IÒ .delims ysiaD
Ó.flesym fo loof a ekam dÕI
,gib esoht fo eno ot
.sregnessap gnikat ton ro demlehwrevo ylbaborp era sppa erahs-ediR
Ó?siht tuoba enoyreve llet ot gniog erÕew gniyas uoYÒ
.ydob reH .tnecs reH
.edaf ot gninnigeb saw thgil larutaN
,etaf ylsirg sih denigami eh sA ?rehtob yhw
.yletaidemmi ti gnizingocer ,dias ysiaD
,deksa ociR Ó?ti si emit tahWÒ
,gnirulla yrev era sdihcrO
,gnigrus enilanerdA
,ecaps dray erom detnaw I .puYÒ
,ylprahs mih kcurts xamilc sÕociR
Ó?smlif orehrepus otni yllaer ton É hu ,mÕI .oNÒ
!eetnaraug nedlog ym sÕtahTÒ ,dekaeuqs dna
.kaew seenk sÕociR edam taht eno ehT
.swen gninrom eht no si meht fo enO  .ecim tsevrah owTÒ
Ó.retfa gninrom eht saW
É tsuj saw I ... rof uoy devol evÕIÒ
.rood eht hguorht draeh eb ot eciov sih gnisiar ,dias eh Ó,haeYÒ Ó?ociRÒ
.noiger eritne eht rof
,kcalb hctip saw tIÒ
.kcab enohp sih tup dna dehgis eH
deb eht ot tnew ociR
.tsaf emac eugitaF
.gnihcuot seson ,yawa sehcnI
Ó?wonk uoy ,tuo em gnipleh rof sknaht
Ó.llihc os era sarabypac uoY
.ria moordeb ,dloc eht ot desopxe meht gnivael
.eci htiw revo dekac yletelpmoc saw ssalg ehT
Ó.dab eb ot evah tÕnod sterceSÒ
Ó.enif eb llÕI erus mÕIÒ
.ociR ot esac eht gnissot
!hctaw nac ew sgniht rehto era
Ó.ladnacs a esuac thgiM
,hu ,tuB .reffo eht etaicerppa IÒ
.krims a mih evag arabypac dekan yldehsabanu ehT Ó.meht deeNÒ
,gnileef eht wenk knumpihc ehT
,dekcoc srae ,flesmih degguh eH
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil erÕuoY
Õ!tfig eht rof uoy knahtÔ kciuq A
arabypac a dna ,nwod dellor wodniw ehT
Ó.sdne ÕnoddegamwonSÔ revenehw ro
Ó,snroh htiw yug a tuoba yas yeht tahw wonk uoYÒ
.retsdwel a mÕI skniht ylbaborP
Ó.hcum sa derugif IÒ
.dlohserht a dessorc dah pihsnoitaler rieht dna
.esolc os ,oS .esolC
,ekil É otni erom mÕIÒ .cipot lanigiro eht ot nruter ot deirt eh
.nihc sih no delbbin ehS
.ociR ,teehs eht porDÒ Ó É lleWÒ
.yas ot tahw wonk neve tÕndid eH .ti tuhs nehT
wodniw eht tuo tnew lla tI
revo saw eivom eht nehW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.cirtcele tlef htob yeht tub
.elam rellams eht pota yaw reh gnirevuenam
,ecuas araniram htiw initor inihccuZ
.raugaj dettops a ,ylliT dias
.hguoht ,llew sa tsuJ .gnihtoN
.tcejbus eht egnahC
,thgiarts pu doots eH
.eciffo ym ni peels ot evah llÕI
Ó.llet nac senileF .ot deen tÕnseoDÒ
.noitcart retteb rof sevooh reh no
Ó,morf emac taht erehw sesion erom tol a sÕerehTÒ
Ó?desserd teg ot deen I od yhW
.liat sih ta debbarg eH
,ria rof pu emac ociR nehW
.steknalb dna steehs eht rednu gnilggirw ylkciuq
.deppots htob yeht ,rehto hcae revo gnikaepS ÓÑyllaer mÕIÒ
Ó!ociR !yeh ,hOÒ
,floWcaM boR si sihT  .goD
.em rof tsuj ton ,yleruS .derednow ociR
!dnekeew lla ereh kcuts eb thgim eH
.tlih a ot yltcerid knas ehs sa ,detnurg ociR
.yaw gnorw ro thgir on sÕerehT
.kcatta cinap a evah dÕI ,thgin eht fo elddim eht ni rood moordeb ym no kconk a yb pu nekow saw I fI
Ó.uoy knahT !hcum ,seYÒ
Ó.em egludni ot nosaer erom eht llAÒ
.sreh htiw ydob rellams sih gnirevoc yletelpmoc ,mih pota gniyal
.smra sÕrehto hcae ni peelsa llef yehT
ÓtsafkaerB erofeB evoLÒ   yojne esaelP
.no tlebtaes sih dah eh erus ekam ot dekcehc-elpirt eH
,yaw eht lla ,reh ni deirub saw eH
.kcalc-kcilC .kcalc-kcilC .langis nrut eht no dekcilf dna enal nrut tfel eht ni tog ehs
Õ,ydnI no seyEÔ saw decudorp eh swohs eht fo enO
.sgninrom yadrutaS
,hOÒ .tibah suovren A
,gnizilaer yllanif ,deknilb eH
,yraurbeF-dim ,noonretfa ywons
.wonk ot gniht eno saw ti tuB
.ssenkrad gnihcaorcne eht otni ylprahs tuc sthgildaeh ehT
.kcen sih dnuora gniog smra ,derumrum ysiaD
.deilper ,eram onimolaP a
,ti eparcs ot gniog saw eH
,gnolbo sti kcuts
,htaerb fo trohs ylgnisaercnI
.teiuq os saw esuoh ehT .gnihtoN
.esolc mih gnigguh ,mih dnuora gniog smra ,derumrum ehs
.ladep eht no nwod dehsup ysiaD dna
.edis eht no dalas dessot a
.reh ta gnillup ,sedis reh ta gnibbarg ,deirc eh Ó!hAÒ
,dereffo ehs Ó,ni poHÒ
Ó.gninrom yadnuS tsael ta litnu su htiw eb lliw sllihc dniw dloc ylsuoregnad dna llafwonS !thgir sÕtahTÒ
Ó,edun mÕI sselnu peelsa llaf tÕnac IÒ .llac dooG
Ó.dloc steg ti erofeb laem ruo tae retteb eW
.retrats nezorf a ro yrettab daed a ylbaborPÒ Ó.thgim ti tuB
,pu tas dna tsehc sih ffo dehsup arabypac eht sa
Ó?wonk uoy ,nwo ym evah yllanif ot ecin eb lliW
Ó?won rats oediv a eb ot gniog erÕuoy ,hu ,oS
.rettoh neve eb ot detnaw eH
Ó?tnaw I tahw erus ton mÕI fi tahWÒ
.rewolf eht ta gniffins ,top eht pu dleh eH ?oN
,tuo ekam ot ysae tÕnerew sliated ,krad eht nI
.rehtie ,tuoba dessarrabme eb ot gnihton evÕuoY
Ó?gnittes laciport ,mraw a htiw gnihtemos ,hoO
.dias arabypac eht
,mlif a esohc ehS
.gnineppah ton si sihT Ó.timmaDÒ
.mih dnA .reh tuobA
.ylliT ,hsittiks ton mÕIÒ Ó.esroh eht syaSÒ
?ssel on ,yaD sÕenitnelaV nO .stnalp eninimef
evah llÕeWÒ .wodniw tseraen eht ot derutseg ehS
.niaga dezigolopa eh Ó,yrros mÕIÒ
.rotavele eht fo tuo tog eh sa noos sa ti raeh dluoc
.eciov reh draeh eh nehw
Ó.enoyna tsuj ot sdihcro tuo evig tÕnod I
,elims a decrof ociR Ó?uoy rof yehT
Ó.ereht revo sÕreyalPÒ
.niaga elims taht delims arabypac ehT Ó.gnitseretnIÒ
:top eht ot dehcatta saw eton ykcits neerg-emil A
.detlit selzzuM .depmub sesoN
yeht nehW .gniyfsitas yltnecifingam
.teerts sÕarabypac eht otno nrut eht gnikat
Ó,em deen uoy fi llah eht nwod eb llÕIÒ
,ydnaM Ó,yas tÕnseod tIÒ
,renroc a dnuora gnikeeP
,ksa ot deppots neht
:edis sulp eht nO
,yzzid saw eh wenk ylno eH
É nruter ni gnihtyna reh teg tÕndid I tuB .detatiseh eH
Ó?ti ekil uoYÒ .noissessop dezirp a ekil
Ó.esuom a htiw lerriuqs a dessorc uoy fi ,ekiLÒ .dediced yaK
.sserttam eht tsniaga nwod mih gnihsup ,gninnip
.tuo daeh delzzum-tnulb
?reh no hsurc a evah I timda ot em teg ot gniyrt ehs sI
.gnilggig fo etaps rehtonA
.kaelb os dekool ti
,llat dna kciht erew sarabypaC
dellac margorp ylkeew a detsoh ohw tsilarutlucitroh a saw
.noitome htiw dedoolf
,tfos saw eciov sÕysiaD
wohs eht dnif ro
.dekool tÕnevaH .ylbaborp ,naem I
.pit eht gnisaet bmuht
,citats fo tib a ,gnissih thgil emoS
.erom neve fo esimorp eht ta gnileer dna erusaelp htiw deldda dnim ,detsisni eh
,saw ti sa yad eht ni etal sa dna ,gnitteg saw rehtaew eht sa dab sA
worromot rac ruoy rof kcab uoy gnirb nac IÒ
moor kaerb dellaw-nepo eht morf dellips noitasrevnoc lausac dna
Ó.yrots retteb a rof ekam dluoc ti tuBÒ .dekniw ysiaD
,yleritne seidob rieht ffo dna kcab reh ffo dils yeht dna ,steehs eht fo kcart tsol ehS
.siht fo yna yb denrecnoc mees tÕndid arabypac ehT
Ó.naem I tahw wonk uoYÒ Ó?citauqAÒ
.worromot rof esrow neve saw tsacerof eht tuB
Ó.rewol hcum leef lliw ti tub
uoy revetahw od nac uoYÒ
,daor eht no kcab seyE
Ó?ti tÕnsi ,terces krad ,peed ruoy sÕtahTÒ
,revo dna pu ti dellup ehs sa daeh sih detsiwt ociR
.evren eht dnif tÕndluoc eH
eno siht piks esaelp
,deb reh otni dednuob dna
Ó.worromot rac ruoy hctef ot
.ylleb dna tsehc sih gnikorts ,dias ysiaD
,dias tsuJ .wonk tÕndid eH
.gnihtemos ro anigav reh em gnivig
Ó!srobhgien wen evah I ,trohs yrots gnoLÒ
.nwotnwod spots wef a edam I ,sdrawretfA
.swap-toof sih dnuora detcelloc tI
,yadnuS ,wonk uoy É ro
.elppin a revo bmuht sih nar yltneg ociR  ?od I od tahW
,arabypac a ,ysiaD .delims ociR
gninedrag dna srewolf tuoba ecivda wotseb ylippah ysiaD ot gninetsiL
,evol tuoba yad a roF
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
.edisni kcab ti ekam neve tÕnod I teB
.ti denepo ehS Ó.drac a sÕerehTÒ
,tsehc sÕociR no wap eno gnitnalp ,drawrof detlit
Ñgnieb tuohtiw moor eht tsap kaens ot deirt ociR
erif no mÕI ekil leeFÒ ,dias ehs
.ecnedicnioc a saw taht fi derednow eH
.elims gnirussaer A
.meht tsuj saw tI
.desuma demees ,gniwohs hteetkcub ,arabypac ehT
!ecnad nac enoyrevEÒ
erÕuoYÒ .elims kciuq a mih dehsalf arabypac ehT
Ó.erofeb lla ti nees evÕI
.won ,toh oot tsomla mÕI .ytsaot oS
.yltnatsni reh gnizingocer ,dias ociR Ó!ysiaDÒ
.ylniatrecnu deticer eh Ó?raM-leD atsiV
Ó,ti sah ecalp siht dna
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.seye reh otni dekool eh
ÓÑelttil a mÕI É mÕIÒ
,tol gnikrap eht nI        .retniw etah I
.nwod meht gnignirb
Ó?neht ,llub taht htiw pu uoy tes llÕI ,oSÒ
Ó.ereht kool tÕndiDÒ
Ó.puY .heHÒ Ó?noitats VT ehTÒ
.gnilwarc evoba secap wef a saw ciffarT
gniteeM ?tontahw ,gnitnalp ,srewolf tuobA
.ffo gnivom dna gniddon
.detlem yllacitcarp eH
.sessik htiw skeehc sih gnireppep ,deilper ehs
Ó.ecaps gnihtynA ?ffuts if-ics
.kcen sih ot nwod gnilzzun ,sehcuot sih ni gnithgiled ,derepsihw ysiaD
.sgnitniap rewolf suomaf esoht nees evÕI
!cituepareht os saw
ro saw ti emit tahw wonk tÕndid eH .derepmihw ociR
Ó.eebraguS ro psircrevEÒ
!haG É tsuj I É dna
.dehtoos ehs Ó,yako sÕtIÒ
Ó.ylisae taht em fo dir gnitteg ton
Ó!eno esoohc ylno nac uoY
,ehtaerb ylerab dluoc
fo tnelaviuqe eht É ekil ,si sihT
Ó?liat ruoy dniheb sÕtahWÒ
.hguorht pils ot hguone ediw ti gnuws eh sa dekaerc tI