.evom ot lliw eht dnif regnol on dluoc I dna tuo em dekconk dah erusaelp ehT
.luftcepsersid yrev gnihtemos yas ot tuoba saw I taht gnisilaer
.ereht nworht ylpmis sehtolc tnereffid htiw derevoc dna edamnu saw deb ehT
htmraw emos revocer ot eidooh ym ni flesym depparw I
.gnikees erew straeh ruo tahw rof
,yltneg ti gnipsarg
eniuqe eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
”…evah yeht esuaceB“
.noiger eht fo sniatnuom dna stserof eht ni gninnur dna gniklaw yb tbuod on degrof
.gnol os rof siht uoy llet ot detnaw evah I
.em nihtiw peed morf eciov siht draeh I
”.lautir eht rof gniraperp hsinif ot deen eW“
niaga kaeps ot detnaw I
.wam sih morf gnippird muc nwo ym htiw deniats saw ruf yM
,erofeb syad wef A
.sgnaf htiw waj lufrewop a otni
”...wehttaM ,hcum os uoy evol I“ .sexes ruo fo
diuqil der eht morf detrats spord ehT
”.dneirf ym ,gnitniap taerg siht naht tnednelpser erom era uoY“
.derrulb won erew sepahs tnatsid dna
.eb ot saw I namuh eht rof dluow ti sa detsugsid ro
,maercs ot detnaw I
.dlrow rehtona saw tI ...llems
erutseg a ni enim tsniaga osrot sih neht dna daeh sih tsrif debbur eH
liat ym fo edisrednu eht gnihsurb erew setset siH
.tnemom emas eht ta sruf ruo gniraems saw I sa
,doohnam sih tuoba gniklat ton m'I ,esruoc fo ,dnA .elttil oot ron
.efil dna rehto hcae tuoba ytisoiruc ruo ni sa
.gnilggurts deppots I dna
”.su ot htrib evag taht tiripS eht saw
.ega ym nosrep a deciton I no rehtruf elttil A
;hteet fo tes yppols yrev a gniwohs
.namuh a sa krow t'nseod flow A .yrrow t'noD“
.ti rebmemer nac I sa yllufhtiaf sa yrots ym uoy llet lliw I ,oS
,yllufecaep peelsa llef yllanif I
.degnahc I sa gnitrotnoc flesym leef dluoc I
.slamina llams desahc dna ,stnalp deffins
.elims citehtapmys a htiw em derussaer eH ”.yrrow t'noD“
ervaH tseW fo seitnuoc eht hguorht gnissap saw
mih ot tuo dellac I dah renoos oN .dnah ym gnivaw
no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,nhinnaT yb
,tliub-llew dna tnecer rehtar erew erofeb tnemom a nees dah I sgnillewd eht fI
rehgih gnisir saw nooM ehT
...siht taht raelc s'tI
.sesnes rehto ym erew
.tnemtnioppasid ni dehgis I
retaerg hcum a ot edulerp eht
;srodirroc eht ni eno on saw erehT
.denialpmoc I ”…emoclew a tahW“
.pohskrow eht raen tsehc a ot tnew dna
”?siht esuac ot od ew did tahw
.dnah ni sreeb ,noitcerid ruo ni gnikool erew yeht dna
”.eciohc on dah I tub
.reppart a fo erutalucsum tsubor eht htiw tub mils saw eH
.yllausac deb eht no nwod tas eH
.mih fo tnorf ni senur suoirav tup ot ybraen nwod tas dna erif eht til eh ,dehsinif I sA
.eno yllanif erew ew
”?em raeh yllaer uoy naC“
”?ereh esilobmys lamina siht seod yltcaxe tahW“
.ereh sgniht ruoy tup nac uoY“ .os erom ton fi
,ebirt eht tuoba stnerap ym deksa I nehw semit esoht osla erew erehT
.sloot suoirav fo tol a sa llew sa ,edistuo gniyl erew setarc wef A
dah I namuh eht fo em dednimer mih tuoba gnihtyrevE
.regnol dna renniht gnitteg erew sbmil yM
.yltneg em dekcil dna ti ot eson sih tup eh dna dnah ym tuo dehcaer I
.yaw etamitni erom neve na ni niaga ti did eH
.desuap eH ”.yltcaxe toN“
.sevlesruo llits erew ew
.ydob sih fo stnemevom lufecarg wef a rof tpecxe deneppah gnihton ,tsrif tA
,tluda gnuoy a sa ,nehw yad eht htiw nigeb lliw I
,tsrif ta ytluciffid htiW
”.flesym yojne llits nac I dna
.atikI fo llems teews eht htiw dellif saw ecalp eht taht desilaer I nehT
...em tsurT .lautir eht gnirud dnatsrednu ll'uoY“
.sehtolc lairtsudni ni stirips erutan htiw enummoc t'nod uoY
tnemom taht ta gnileef saw eh erusaelp eht enigami dluoc I
.tuo dna ni sivlep sih evom ot nageb eH .tsul dna
.ylpeed ruf sih llems ot ytinutroppo eht koot dna
,seye ym otni dekool eH
.deticxe erom neve saw I ,yrartnoc eht nO
.os did I sa dias I
.nerdlihc erew ew nehw remmus eht ni esuoh eht ot emac netfo atikI
llih llams a ro eert a no sucof ot emit evah t’ndid seye yM
suoesuan em edam evah thgim taht sesion gnikcus htiw sevlesmeht gnignarraer erew sedisni yM
?em htiw gnidnopserroc pots uoy did yhW“
arE wen a sdrawoT"
.erofeb htiw epoc yldrah dluoc I taht em ni sgnileef dekove tI
.efil tneduts deyojne dna ,seivom dehctaw ,skoob daer I
eno siht piks esaelp
,revewoh ,tsom em kcurts tahW
.redlo hcum saw eno siht
.yks eht ot esor ylwols dna
.gniklat dna ,gnikooc ,gninaelc ,sesuoh citsur rieht fo tnorf ni enituor yliad rieht tuoba tnew nemow dna neM
,nawor neeb evah tsum taht redwop kcalb siht htiw derevoc neht saw eno hcaE
,yadot trats ot si noitaitini ruoY
.taht ekil adnik ,haeY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tserof eht fo egde eht sdrawot devom eh
.htuom ym morf emac elgrug a tub gnihton tub
,yldneirf wef a tuo tel daetsni dna
dessarrabme gnileef tuohtiw yerp tsrif ym fo doolb eht detsat I
.ecarbme knarf a htiw mih democlew dna smra ym denepo I
,em fo tnorf ni thgiR
.shpylg labirt werd taht yaw a ni decalp senots htiw aera egral a dnuora stnirptoof ynam htiw neddort saw htrae ehT
ylneddus pu doots eH
.noziroh eht revo saw
rewsna ot detnaw I
,atikI ot deit llitS
.tsehc ym no ruf eht dekorts ylrednet
snoitanigami ruo ni hcum os derahs eW
”.uoy htiw erom enod evah dluoc I hsiw I“
”!uoy llet I ,lerutan uA
msagro gniogno ym morf demlehwrevo llits saw I
...ev'I“ ”?degnahc tahW“
.degnahcnu deniamer seye sih fo epahs ehT
llams ni tuo hsug diulf eninac ym tlef dna
.sgol rif eht gninrub erif eht dna
.ssender sti tsol erif eht dna dedaf sruoloc ehT
,eirudA fo ecnivorp eht fo erutceferp eht ,trofuaeB morf emac I
,ylippah detuohs I ”!atikI“ .mih
.atikI deksa I
,tnemom a detsal ylno ti tub
”?wonk uoy ,siht ekil uoy nees ev'I emit tsrif eht ton s'tI .ttaM ,looC“
.yretsym fo lluf seye htiw em ta gnirats dna
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sseddog ruoy si nooM ehT
strups evisseccus
.dehsinif atikI litnu ,sselnoitom
”yaW floW eht ot noitaitinI yM“ saw sihT
.ydob sih morf cirbaf fo tib yreve gnivomer dehsinif eh
ruf fo tib nellows taht ot resolc gnitteg erew skcil yM
.seirrac doolb ruo taht ycagel eht dna
.suna ym gniyarps erew lasuora sih fo seciuj ehT
.luos ruoy fo rorrim eht si egami yM
yrfleb eguh a fo dnuos eht ekil dnim ym ni deohce ,dnatsrednu ylerab
ytingid ym fo tfel saw tahw werdhtiw I
mih dnuora swap ym depparw tsuj I
.enim sa emas eht saw
,deid daD ecniS“ .deb
:smeti lareves tuo koot eH
.mih htiw ssarg eht ni ereht yal dna
.dneirf doohdlihc ym fo
,retteb hcum saw gniraeh yM
gnittis saw flow etihw yltcefrep a
,gnirahs ruo ,gnimoc yM
.ereht nrob ton saw I hguohtla
.dlrow laer eht ot kcab em thguorb niap tneloiv a ,ecno ta llA
.nwod elttes ot ekil tsael ta d'I ?tahW“ ".etal
.deeps hgih a ta yb welf epacsdnal ehT
.enim no tsehc sih detser dna
.gniraelc egral a ot emac ew litnu tserof peed eht ni ruoh elohw a rof deklaw eW
llew sa seitivitca dna
sertem nezod wef a rof no tnew eW
”.em erofeb thgir tis dna emoC“
,gnithgif ,dnuorg eht no gnillor
.gniraelc eht fo egde eht ta sehsub eht ni neddih tuh a dehcaer dna stnatibahni sti fo weiv lluf ni egalliv eht hguorht dessap eW
.tonk gniddub sih fo sepahs eht leef dluoc I
.mutorcs ym dniheb egassap eht derevocsid dna
yllaer dluoc I .meht erofeb dessap eh sa dneirf ym deteerg lla yehT
”,gnol os neeb s'ti ,wehttaM“
.em ta devaw dna elttob sih detfil eh
eduteiuq a fo erus
.nosrep tnatropmi na I ma ron
.ydob sih fo enil lufecarg ehT
.saw ti tahw ot denruter reven dna
.neht ereh eb ot dewolla eb ot uoy ot ti ewo I“
no gniog saw gnihtemoS
.dneirf ym deksa I
,htuom sih ni dellews tonk yM
.em ees ot yppah ylemertxe demees dna
.taorht ym morf emac repmihw eninac evitnialp a tub
”.wehttaM ,ylluferac snoitcurtsni ym wolloF“
.srettel ym rewsna t'ndid dna
”,ecalp gnitseretni na ni evil uoY“
yrruh a ni puc ym dehsinif dna kcapkcab ym debbarg I
”.enog s'eh taht won ebirt eht fo namahs eht m'I
,emit eht ta namuh llits saw I hguoht nevE
,enipul a ni delims dna
.lrufnu dna enips ym morf egreme liat a tlef I sa
depahs oot rehtien ,tnecifingam
ytterp kool ll'yeht taht epoh eht ni rehtegot sdrow gnirts ot gniyrt flowerew yllis a si ohw ,nhinnaT yb
”...tnereffid yna yllaer ton s'tI“
.noitidart morf yawa ylimaf a detrats dna nairarbil a sa dekrow I
.loohcs nredom a ot tnew I ,meht ekilnU
.emas eht od dna pu yrruh dnA
,degnahc dah sruoloc ehT
.ecaf lacitpecs yrev a ees ot dnuora denrut eH
”.su rof gnitiaw neeb evah ot kool yehT“ ”.snorom era yehT“
.srotsecna ym fo dnal eht
”.dnatsrednu noos ll'uoY“
.morf emac ew erehw tegrof ton od ew taht os
...uoy did tahw dnA“ ”.su ekil yllaer
nibac ym fo tuo gnippets erofeb
.stoob tabmoc derettab dna snaej eulb nrow
atikI smeti suoirav eht htiw tuo tnew eW
.hctorc ym morf yawa daeh sih gnillup
.pets kciuq a htiw mih dewollof tsuj I taht
.ti dehcaer eugnot nwo sih nehw sih sa etats emas eht ni saw ycamitni nwo ym taht desilaer I
.niap hcum os ni t'nsaw I fi
.eciov lanoitome na ni deirc tsomla eH
,egatireh ruoy no ekaT .em saw ti ,oN
eulb tcefrep a saw yks ehT
.won thgir reganeet a ekil kool t'ndid eh tub
,tnelis yltcefrep tsomla gnivom saw hcihw ,niart ehT
.dessorc senil eht erehw stniop ta shpylg eht dnuora ylneve decalp erew seldnac ehT
.eciov peed a ni derepsihw eH
taht gniksam ylerab moor eht dedavrep tsudwas fo llems tnasaelp a ,ylgnisirpruS
.no raewrednu ym ylno dah I litnu deunitnoc I tub
,noziroh eht no wol llits ,nus ehT
********** .ytiralc latsyrc htiw ti rebmemer llits I
”.uoy ot gniklat erew nemsebirt eht yaw eht
;retnuoc eht dniheb luos gnivil a ton saw erehT
.mrof lanigiro ruo ni sa
nriac ruo ot levart ot dah I taht dna
eert nawor eht fo taht saw deviecrep I llems tsrif ehT
,ti tuoba yppah saw I ,revewoH
.esuoh ym dniheb evorg eht gnirolpxe
namuh a fo taht regnol on saw ydob yM
.ni em detivni dna
.erehw dna ecalp ot tahw em dlot ylesicerp dna yltneitap atikI
.detseggus dneirf tseb yM
.egassem siht eviecer ot desirprus saw I ,oS
,level sti ta ecnO .eson ym fo
.tliub dah ew ned eht dnuora
.traehteews doohdlihc dna dneirf ym tsuj
.ereh yaw eht lla emoc ot eno ylno eht neeb evah tsum I
.egnarts saw edutitta tnalahcnon sih dna
,nataQ fo dnalretnih eht otni thgir
,neetfif tuoba erew ew nehw tuB
dluoc I hcihw ,sdrow ehT
steknirt edamdnah ynam htiw pohskrow a saw renroc eno nI .tsenoh eb ot
.detanicsaf saw I hcum os ti derimda dna ti ta derats I
seirots noitcif ecneics dna ysatnaf setirw ohw dna
,ylsuoveihcsim dias eH
.tnemeerga ni daeh ym deddon I
smotsuc ruo ot gnidrocca noitaitini fo ega eht dehcaer dah I taht em gnillet
rorroh fo noisiv a dewollof erehT
.yteritne sti ni nwod ti etirw ot detnaw I
.rewsna on deviecer tub
.spil sih yb pu delruc niks ym
.kool derit dna nrow a htiw em ta gnirats saw eH
erom yas ot deen oN
.noitadipert emos tuohtiw ton tub
,enim ot esolc ecaf sih decalp dna
em sdrawot daeh sih denrut eH
,trihs dekcehc kcalb dna der elpmis a gniraew saw eH
.erom etirw ot derit oot ma I ,won roF
.trihs-T ym yb dewollof eidooh nottoc ym ffo koot I
,gnis egailof eht gnikam saw dniw ehT
.ereh dekooc neeb dah taem emag ,erofeb yad eht taht wenk I
.detarepsaxe dekool dna desuap eH
,niks eht dennod eh sA
”.meht rof hguone s'tahT .tsixe eW“
,oda rehtruf tuohtiW
,em naht rellams llits saw eH
stirips live tnuh dluow eW
.niart eht ffo tog I nehw erofeb ereht saw tnecs taht fo yteltbus ehT
,sraey rof no gnikrow neeb s'eh sesrevinu ni
ecnatsiser tlef I
.noitats eht ot ecnartne eht sdrawot ffo tes ew dna
.sdnoces wef a rof thguoht I
htuom ym otni erom tohs rebmem sih morf eslup A
,namuh a sa decneirepxe saw I
.telmah eht hguorht gninnur maerts eht fo gnippal eht raeh ot em gniwolla
pu denethgiarts eH
dnoces a naht erom em ekat t'ndid tI
.ytivissap ym deciton noos eh dna
,noitca ym deunitnoc I .gnihtyreve
pu dedne shtap ruo fi neve
railimaf saw ezag siH
.og flesruoy tel dna
.eciov sih fo dnuos lufituaeb eht ylno saw erehT
I gnihtemos saw erehT
!emit tsrif eht ton s'tI !yako s'tI“
.erom ecno em kcil ot em ot resolc devom eh sa
.tcaer ro dnopser t'ndluoc dna
.noziroh eht ot gnihcterts loop ydoolb toh a emaceb dnuorg ehT
.em ot delaever saw ycamitni s'atikI sa
.nihtiw morf deliob doolb yM
.smraf eht dna nialp neerg diviv eht no swodahs citsejam werd
.yaw ym ni desohpromatem atikI hcihw ni
”yaW floW eht ot noitaitinI
rehtie tuo tfel ton saw I
.slamina llams dna stcesni fo sdnuos eht gniynapmocca
”!atikI ,daeha oG“
.sgnirehtag rof desu ylraluger saw ti taht ees ylraelc dluoc I
.ytixelpmoc dna yteltbus sti htiw
.tnemeticxe dna evol sih esnes dluoc I
.seiriuqni ym rewsna ot desufer syawla dah yeht tub
.pots ton dluow taht msagro siht yb dedavni eb flesym tel dna nwod eil ot krow ym deppots I
tcnitsni yb serutseg sih ot dednopser I
.dehca ydob ym sa
tey tsuj pots ot gniog t'nsi gnileef er'uoy erusaelp sihT
,ylleb sih sdrawot devom elzzum ym ,yllarutaN
.yltnecer litnu ton tsael tA
.deilpmoc I ,erom neve gnihsulB
.gnihgual ,denialpxe eH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.mih rof gnitiaw deppots dah I
.yaw nwo sih llits tub
.egA enotS eht ot denruter dah I fi sa tlef I
,tluciffid tib a syawla si emit tsrif ehT“
.lufituaeb llits saw eh ,flow a sa nevE
ylno saw ylimaf ym ni dewolf taht doolb eht dna
.ytisnetni ni deilpitlum msagro yM
”.oot flesruoy yojne dna
.degnahc dah atikI hcum woh derednow I
htiw yarrasid ni moor elgnis a dnuof I
,nemsebirt eht dna sretnuh eht fo ruoivaheb eht neewteB
.sretnuh ekil dekool ohw elpoep fo elpuoc a htiw kcurt pukcip a deciton I dna
.ruoivaheb siht denoitseuq reven I
,deyalpsid yltnenimorp erew selfir riehT
”.sniev ruo ni tiripS floW eht fo doolb eht yrrac ylpmis eW“
”?yeht era kcuf eht ohW“
flesti gniraperp ydaerla saw doohnam sih taht deciton yllautneve I dna
.em detartenep yletaidemmi eh sa
,gnihton dias atikI
.delbmuts yletaidemmi tub
,gnorw ylraelc saw gnihtemoS
demrofsnart saw rellewd ytic a sa efil ym
.em detagujbus dna
pots a ot emac eh litnu setunim wef a rof detsal erusaelp sihT
.gnivael saw I taht ylimaf ym llet ot emit hguone tsuj dah neht dna
,srehto ynam ekil nataQ fo evitan elpmis a ma I
.em ot railimaf saw hcihw ereht telmah llams a saw erehT
eht no sehtolc ym werht dna
atikI dneirf doohdlihc ym morf rettel a deviecer dah I
.ssendas fo egnit a htiw tub
.llems sih ni rewen neve gnihtemos desnes I
erew ew ohw fo tfel gnihtemos tnaw I
”...itsrepus fo lluf saw aera eht taht nettogrof dah I .ees I“
.enola sluos ruo hguorht
”?ti si ,sreganeet gnuoy erew ew nehw sa emas eht ton s'tI“
.ezag sih tuoba ekil t'ndid
,elbarapesni erew eW
”.yas thgim uoy ,sepirts denrae
,em revo doots atikI
niart elbaliava tsrif eht koot I taht os hcum os
.ti morf dedaeb taht diuqil egnarts eht detsat I
:ksa uoy erofeb dnA
.sehsub dna seert eht hguorht mih retfa nar dna ylper on edam I
.fo gninaem eht dnatsrednu dluoc I
.hcuot hcae htiw ylthgils gnitcartnoc dna gnitcaer saw ydob siH
em gnidiova erew yeht taht ylkciuq etiuq deciton I ,revewoH
.em gnirewsna erofeb dehgis eH .atikI deksa I
.xes ym revo ylsuoiruf gnidils saw ylleb sih fo ruf eht
”...gnorw saw I ylraelc tub
.fo erac koot ylsuoivbo eh hcihw
.emit gnol a rof rehto hcae moorg ot deunitnoc dna ,edis yb edis ,nwod yal eW .deviecrep dah
,ytiliga taerg htiw depmuj eW
em edisni noitome fo hsur a tlef I
.suoires etiuq dekool eH
.gnikil s'enoyreve ot ton saw lavirra ym dna
.s'esle enoemos ta gnikool erew I fi sa
doohdlihc ruo ni tnemssarrabme fo stnemom eseht derebmemer I
floW eht fo yaw eht ot noitaitini yM
”…dekan eb ot evah ew yhw em llet tsael ta d'uoy fI“
”?ti t'nsi ,gniht ecin a si flow eht fo ssenknarf ehT“
,wehttaM ,yaw eht fo tuo liat ruoy teG“ .delims eH
,hteet ym did sa ,werg eson dna htuom yM
.tnemele larutan ym ni tlef I
.ylsuounitnoc detalucaje I sa evom ot detnaw spih yM
si elbbircs tsetal sih hcihw fo
”…dna sruoh ytnewt rof niart eht no neeb ev'I
.thgiew sih rednu desserpmoc gnieb slatineg ym leef dluoc I dna
”.wenk syawla I“
.ssenredliw eht ni sruoh ynam rof nar eW
.em sdrawot gninnur ydaerla saw eh naht
”,wehttaM ,etunim a tiaW“
.ylthgils pu tas I
.nageb dna seye sih desolc eh ,gnitiaw tuohtiW
.gnihcuot tsomla seson ruo
eht no gab ym gniworht ,dias I
em detacixotni tI
.ecnartne eht dnif ot sinep sih fo pit eht eborp mih tlef I
”?ew llahs ,pu hctac s'teL“
.spley etanoitceffa
,sraey eseht lla retfA
.yltpurba em detpurretni eH
.thgis fo tuo erew yeht litnu detiaw I
.llah eht ni lacirtcele gnihtyna ro sthgil yna ees t'ndluoc I
”.tuo gninnur si emit dnA !eromyna ton s'ti tuB .eurT“ ”.erofeb
,em morf rewsna na rof gnitiaw tuohtiW
.sega eht fo thgiew eht dewohs dna krad saw doow ehT
.detarapes yllaturb gnieb
.ylwols em dehcaorppa dna pu doots eH
,xes ym dnuora elzzum sih fo htmraw eht tlef I sa
sa dnal siht fo snaidraug eht era eW“
.aelp a tsomla saw ecaf sih no kool ehT ”?esaelp
”.egamoh mih yap netfo eW
,emit emas eht tA
.sretsis dna srehtorb rieht morf efil tnereffid a em reffo ot gnuoy llits erew yeht nehw dnal ruo tfel dah stnerap yM
”.srettel ym fo yna derewsna reven uoY
”.renoos uoy dlot evah dluoc I
em dedavni noitcelfer reH
”.emit on yllaer s'ereht ,ttaM“
uoy ot emoc taht snoisiv eht no sucof ot si
,noitaitini ym dehsinif I nehW“
,em ta gnilims saw eno redlo ehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
...t'nod yehT .ylimaf yhpruM eht fo srebmeM“
.kcod eht ot nwod tnew I
”,ecalp ym ot gniog er'eW“ ”...I ,atikI“
.evil ot desu ebirt ym erehw saw sihT
,dna noitatiseh yM
.mih demalb syawla ylbaborp I
.epacsdnal cillydi siht gnihctaw em ot txen gnittis saw atikI
redwop deruoloc-laocrahc fo raj egral a ,senotsenur ,seldnac
.stirips live morf su stcetorp eH
wonk ot uoy tnaw t'ndid sredle eht yas tsuj s'teL“ .yawa dekool dna
.xes ym fo noitcartnoc hcae htiw erusaelp esnetni em gnivig
.nerdlihc llits erew ew nehw
,ecaf ym revo dils liat yhsub sih retfA
.yad rehtona no uoy llet yam I yrots a s'taht tuB
”,meht dnim t'noD“
.elims daorb a htiw em ta derats eh sa
”...wehttaM ,em htiw emoC“
”?esoppus I ,taerg ...s'tahT“
.delaever erew snoitasnes wen sa
,sesnes ym ton ,doolb ym tahw derebmemer I
.niks ym revo werg ruf etihw sa deraeppasid dloc gnitib ehT
,niaga dna niaga ,deslup I
em otni gniruop saw muc siH
.slautir eht etelpmoc ot
”.won su fo eno yllanif er'uoY .revo s'tI“
.taht lla dna secnad dna smurd htiw
mubla dlo ’stnerap ym morf serutcip eht derebmemer I
.su ta gnirats tpek taht puorg eht morf yawa gnivom ,tserof suorefinoc eht sdrawot daor eht gnola gniklaw deunitnoc eW
,erusaelp fo naom a tuo tel tub pleh t'ndluoc I
…atikI uoy evol I“
.gniniatretne erom erew hcihw wenk I taht emos dna sbreh suoirav llems dluoc I dna
.enim dniheb xes dna sivlep sih gnicalp
.ruf sih fo sruoloc eht fo ynomrah ehT
,mra ym no dnah sih decalp eh ,tnahc labirt sih gnippots tuohtiW
.rehtruf yna xaler ot deen t'ndid dna
.em ot gnikaeps flow eht saw tI
gnirewsna morf kcab dleh I
”.os od ot neddibrof saw I“
”…on ,ton ylraelC“
.ebirt eht morf erutraped ’stnerap ym ot detaler saw ti fi rednow ot nageb I
dna em ot revo deklaw dna pu doots eH
.gnitniap s'tsitra taerg a sa lufituaeb sa saw yellav eht revo weiv ehT
tuo nwolf ydaerla dah yeht nehw
”.ot tnaw t'ndid I ekil ton s'tI“
.erofeb em ot neddibrof saw tuoba em dlot uoy noitaitini
tlef ylterces I taht em ni gnignol a denekawa taht gnihtemoS
nageb niar fo dnik A
.lufniap etiuq fi neve enivid saw gnileef wen sihT
gnirevocsider saw I ,flow a sa tub
.erutplucs eht ot resolc teg ot deppots I
riah sih hguorht dnah sih nar atikI
ediw daerps dna pu sgel ym htiw deyats I
.elpmis etiuq dekool edacaf sti dna sgol etihw htiw tliub saw tI
.kool gninoitseuq ym yb dessarrabme ylsuoivbo dekool eH
flow snialp a fo taht saw ruf siH
.regnol yna tsiser ot em rof etuc oot saw eH
.gnihtyna nialpxe ot gnivah mih tuohtiw
ytimixorp eht htiw gniworg saw sinep regae sih hcihw ni
.sserttam eht otno ylpmil deppord dna sgel dna smra sih daerps eH
.nees dah I flow eht fo taht emoceb dah tub
;yaw yna ni em pleh t'ndid hcihw ,emit elohw eht
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
ecnart a ni saw I
.nalC floW eht fo wehttaM
.yks eht llif ot tfel saw noom eht ylno dna deraeppasid tserof eht ylnedduS
.flow tluda na fo taht otni mrofsnart ydob sih fo trap yreve was ylwols I
.dnal desilivicnu na hcus ni ees ot detcepxe I tahw ekilnu t’nsaw ti tub
efil ym fo evol eht saw atikI
dessarrabme os saw I
.sgniteerg nwo ym gnirongi dna
.pets tnedifnoc ,larutan a htiw em dehcaorppa eH ".enola
.mih tsurt ot dediced dna
,yromem ym ni nosrep lufyalp a neeb dah eH
.tnemesuma ni daeh sih koohs dna dehgual atikI
,flesmih derewol eH
drawrof deppets atikI
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,yllabrev kaeps tonnac eW .seY“
em revo emac noitasnes egnarts A
.ereh efil fo ytnelp saw erehT
.krej hcae htiw ylleb ym no nemes ym detisoped ylsuounitnoc rebmem ym elihw
.gnilbbin ,gniffins ,gnikcil
sevlesruo sserpxe ot elba gnieb fo gnisselb eht su reffo stirips flow eht tub
.nerdlihc erew ew nehw ereht neve saw tI
.dnim ym ni draeh I ”,won klat nac eW“
.citsilaer ylemertxe saw ydob eht fo trap hcaE
,ssenilnaelc fo smret ni moor tneduts ym morf tnereffid hcum ton saw moor eht fo tser ehT
,em evig t'ndid eh eciohc eht
stnadnecsed ym ot decneirepxe evah I tahw fo ecart a evael ot tnaw I
”.su ees lliw eno on
.noitats eht ta devirra niart eht nehw aet kcalb ym gniknird llits saw I
,flow on ees dluoc I dna
.nwo ym sa etihw sa erew liat dna ylleb sih elihw krad erew srae sih dna
.sserdnu ot gnitrats ylneddus erofeb elbat eht no ylluferac rettal eht decalp eH .niks flow a
,won nosrep tnatropmi na eb tsum uoY“
,slobmys eseht fo ertnec eht ni tas reizarb dehsiugnitxe na fo sniamer ehT
.etal oot eb lliw ti ro
.esitrepxe dna noitisop sih desilaer I
”.uoy ot dereffo si taht dlrow wen siht revocsid dna em wolloF“
.em demrofni yldas eH ”,sgniht niatrec
”.seitilibisnopser sih dna esuoh eht fo erac ekat ot sah ohw eno eht m'I
,tserof eht ni llits saw I
.yenruoj suoregnad dna
.su raen eutats reednier egral eht desingocer dna
.snoitseuq ym edave dluow atikI nehw
.tsim eht hguorht gniretlif thgilnus fo syar tsal eht htiw gninihs erew sniatnuom derevoc-wons ehT
.decneirepxe reve evah I lacigam tsom eht saw gnineve tahT
elims citamgine na
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht
.tnemom siht fo gnimaerd fo sraey yb deifilpma gnileef a
.tisiv ot emit evah yllaer t'nod eW“
********** .raeppasid reven dluow thguoht I taht
.dengiser ,deksa I ”?tahw woN“ .deb
,seidob tnereffid ni nevE .devol syawla
.keehc sih nwod gninnur saw taht raet eht deird dna
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,seno rehto eht morF
.oot ffo sdaeh rieht gnihgual erew yeht tub
yawa kool t'ndluoc I
.sllab krad sih ot htaehs eht fo elohw eht gnirevoc
.ffilc a fo pot eht dehcaer dna
.gnirednaw sduolc derettacs wef a tsuj htiw
.tserof eht fo naidraug eht s’eH“
,erofeb ereh neeb reven dah I
.suoivbo saw emoceb dah I tahw rof drow eht
,feileb laivirt a tsuj saw ti taht gninrom siht dias evah dluow I“
.yks sselrats a ni gninihs saw nooM ehT
.ezeerb gninrom eht ni gniwolb riah kcalb htgnel-dim
ylluf nwod knas eH
.elzzum ym fo edis eht dekcil ylwols eh sa
.gnignis trats annog m'I ,gnihtoN“
,daor trid eht no gninnur erew nerdlihc gnuoY
,depoleved ylecin erew skcottub dna shgiht siH
,rorroh ni pu tuhs yletaidemmi I
,dlo gnitteg ma I nehw yad siht no ,revewoH
.pit gnidurtorp ylthgils eht ot kcil mrif dna wols a evag I
.stnemurtsni yna yb deinapmocca ton saw atikI ,ereH
.swap sih htiw em gnimarf
…daer ot rotarran eht rof ysae s’ti os stnedni on htiw lairA stp61 si siht dna ,thgin ymrots dna krad a saw tI   .sseddog ruo fo snevaeh eht hcaer slwoh ruoy yaM
.ebirt ym fo erutluc eht tuoba hcum wonk t'ndid I
.tuh eht dniheb dleif eht rof dedaeh dna lautir eht rof dedeen
”.yad lla tog t'nevah eW“ .deksa eH ”?neht lleW“
.enim tsniaga mlap sih gnitser dna nwod gnidils ylwols erofeb
saw osrot sselriah siH
”.dnatsrednu t'nod I“
gnibborht eht leef dluoc I
yM“   yojne esaelP  .remrahc
”?ew t'nera ,sevlowerew era eW“
.em revo lla flesmih daerps dna
.sraey wef a ni degnahc dah eh hcum woh ta dezama saw I
,taht detnaw reven I
.seiduts ym dehsinif tsuj dah I erehw
.elbisiv erew noitcere ym ,deedni
.dnuora dekool dna
,nam taerg a ton ma I
.ekowa I retfa noos nrael ot saw I terces eht ot deit saw gnihtyreve
.erehwyreve gnihtyna dna gnihtyreve
em gnihctaw saw eH
tnaem eh tahw yletaidemmi dootsrednu I
,gnitnahc llits saw atikI
,mih wollof ot em denokceb eH
noitceffa emas eht htiw noitnetta sih denruter I
,yletanoissap debbur selzzum ruO
.raef tuohtiw sthguoht ym desserpxe dah I
”.ti tuoba yrrow t'noD“
.noitazilivic morf raf tub
rewsna ylno sih sa evag dna deggurhs
,sgniht rehto gnoma ,dna
ynoep a ekil gnihsulb ,seye ym derevoc ylkciuq I ”!?lleh eht tahW“
rood eht denepo atikI ”!devirra ev'eW“
,citsejam erew sreltna ehT
.ytiruces fo esnes a em evag dna
.noisiv fo dleif ym fo
.yaw tsegnarts eht ni tub
.dnuorg eht no yltneg tlep sih dial dna kcab deppets eH .dehgis eH
.ecidujerp ym tuoba ytliug tlef I sa derewol srae yM
.siht tuoba em dlot reven dah stnerap yM
od tsum uoy gniht ylno ehT
”!sretsnom elat-yriaf ton era eW“
lufituaeb dah eH
.ysub yrev kool t'ndid ecalp eht
ylthgit em degguh eH
tnatsid emaceb niap ehT
,swohs VT dna skoob fo sepytoerets eht wollof ot slautir ruo detcepxe yllanigiro dah I
.dluoc eh sa drah sa ni dehsup eh dna
,rood tnorf eht hguorht deklaw eW
”yaW floW eht ot noitaitinI yM“
pu doots I .siht ekil gnihtyna nwonk reven dah I
.ylsselerac gnittis
,remmus gniwollof eht kcab emoc dah uoy fI
.ereht erew ohw elpoep eht lla fo ega dna ,redneg ,rebmun eht llet neve dluoc I
.seciov rieht ni tcepser eht leef
.noisreva yna gnileef em tuohtiw
.ecaf ym tib ria looc ehT
”.seirt wef a htiw gnihtyna gnileef pots yllautneve ll'uoy tub
,em revo peerc ot nageb ssendas fo mrof A
.esuoh eht dniheb dray eht ot ffuts siht lla yrrac em pleh woN“
em revo emac erusaelp fo llirht A
.erutnevda tac ysatnaf a ,")retpahC toliP(
delkraps seye depahs-dnomla ,nworb krad siH
.htgnerts erom htiw tub
”?won od I dluohs tahW“
,setunim lareves rof ereht yal I
.em morf tnatropmi gnihtemos gnidih saw atikI taht leef tub pleh t'ndluoc I
.yawa dedaf em dnuora gnihtyreve dna seye ym desolc I nehT
.denetaerht neve ,elbatrofmocnu tlef I
,neht neeb dah eh sa emosdnah sa llits saw eH
,erac t'ndid I tuB
.llems fo esnes ym tuB
.daeh sih dniheb smra ,yawa gniklaw yltnelis erofeb
.sruoy si doolb sihT
ezingocer ot
.ydob yllihc dna dekan ym revo smra ym dedlof I sa tnemesuma dna noitceffa htiw em ta dekool eH
evol ruo fo tnecs eht htiw dellif saw eson yM
,gnicneirepxe saw I tahw ot flesti dengiser dnim yM
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
gnimoc deppots eh
”.enod er'ew nehw thginot peels ot gnihtemos uoy xif ll'I
noitceffa htiw deilper I ”?hu ,sraey xiS“
.em desirprus lamina eht fo sliated ehT
.noitautis eht ni noitercsid fo muminim eht fo derussaer saw I tsael tA
,wehttaM si eman yM  nhinnaT yb
.ffo seit ruo tuc dluohs I taht dediced saw ti
.yltcerroc em thguat dah sessalc ynatob ym fi
.rehtegot su gniyt dna gniworg saw tonk sih wenk I sa em edisni erusserp dna
.nohtaram a gninnur erew ew fi sa gnitnap dna gninaom htob erew eW
,dlihc a sa em detanicsaf taht seirots eht ot gnidroccA
deksa I ”?uoy era ohW“
,enivid os ,nooM eht dna gnimoc saw gnineve ehT
.yks eht ni rehgih dna
.yldrawkwa deilper I
.dnah ym htiw ruf eht leef ylerab dluoc I dna