.ydobyna htiw elttab a ni gnitteg ycnaf hcum t’ndid esnohplA esuaceb
.mih llet I fi mih esol thgim I
,nogaw gnicnuob eht no ecnalab sih peek ot gnitlit dna gnidnats
.ereht no saw esle revetahw dna doolb htiw dexim akdov ytilauq-wol eht gnitsat
,dias xof gnilims eht
?mih rof …yag tsuj ,neht ebyaM
.tliug dna emahs dna tnemssarrabme dna tnemtnioppasid dna evol dna raef dna egar htiw demraws daeh siH
.trac eht dellup ti sa deknalc tcurtsnoc xo lacinahcem eht dna
.daeh sih ni gninrom eht fo stneve eht gniyalper
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”.yawyna pu denaelc teg og dluohs ew ,enif s’tI“
( yllaitini srae sih no depmuj sregnif s’rykeS
”,heh heh ,oot nonnac gib a tog ,hu ,ev’I“
.gnitcepxe saw eh tahw wonk t’ndid yllaer eh ,hguoht ,tsenoh eb oT
.gnirats llits saw regdab ehT
,gnisir noissap ,dellems ksuM
.tnereffid saw tahw ees ot elba saw noitpecrep desaercni s’raeb ehT
.lausu naht ralucsum erom hcum erew yeht tuB
.did yllaer fo dnik eh ,haey
- dneirf tseb sih fo sthguoht sih ot esnopser lacisyhp suoivbo
eno siht piks esaelp
,elzzum sih pu denepo nrohT
.uoy llems dnA
.mih rednu morf tuo sgel sih tpews nrohT sa esirprus yb nekat saw rykeS
.tuo dedriew lla teg thgim eH
.seert eht morf nwod maeb ot gnitrats tsuj nus fo syar tsrif eht htiw
seirraH nomoloS yb
.sllips ezoob ,srettahs ssalG
,dias esnohplA .dnuorg eht ot sinep s’rykeS morf llef ti
,elpmet deniur tneicna na ni elzzup a saw ti fI
.raeb sih morf naom peed dna pmuj a gniticile ,daeh eht tsuj
.yawyna ,gniod saw eh tahw wenk ylekil esnohplA
,rykeS saw siht taht derebmemer eh ,seuqinhcet eugnot tnereffid derolpxe eh sA
– seniledis eht morf gnihctaw enoyna ot woN
?yad yreve taht od eh diD
.erehwon fo tuo noitop delebalnu na knird ot aedi doog a ton s’ti ,yllamron woN
rykeS ta revo dekool dna
.kcolnu ot mih rof ydaer
.mih gnivol pots ot woh tuo erugif I sselnu
dna kcil sih fo erutsiom eht tlef
.selkcat raeb ,segdod xoF
.oot llaf ydob nilbog a was eh thguoht eh
– saw ti gnol woh llet t’ndluoc raeb eht – yllautnevE
,niaga dessik yeht sa seye desolc rieht revo dewolf retaw mraw ehT ~ .delims dna
.dneirf tseb sih otni
.deredisnoc dna dehcraeS
.su neewteb driew sgniht ekam ot ti tnaw t’nod I dnA
,hcae stih doog elpuoc a ni teg ot gniganam ,gnivom tpek riap ehT
.ecaf sih no kool citegolopa na dna
.raor lamirp ,retuc ,rellams ,nwo sih tuo tel dna
- senur eht gnidda trats nac uoy neht ,slairetam thgir eht si tcejbo na wonk uoy ecnO“
.ecafrus eht ot delbbub ti sa gnirongi neeb d’eh tcaf a ecaf ot decrof saw eh
.htrof dna kcab edils ot detrats dna noitisop doog a dnuof xof eht tub
.trid eht otni ffo nellaf dah taht tnadnep elprup gniwolg a pu dekcip dna nwod denael rykeS
,srekcatta gniniamer owt eht fo eno fo redluohs eht otni ti gniworht
.tfahs eht pu yaw eht lla sllab eht morf pu
.thguoht
.ssalg eht pu dekciP
?hcum os mih gnirehtob eb dluoc tahW
.tcaer neve dluoc nilbog eht erofeb
.wonk yllaer t’nod I ,mU“
.oot em evol dluoc eh ebyaM .ebyam ,rO
.sgnileef sih gnidih htiw pu def saw rykeS
.htuom sih ni rettib saw tI
.uoy dloh ot tnaw I
.yadot em fo erac gnikat …roF
.xof taht gnihctaw syojne ylniatrec raeb ehT
,ereht gnidnats mih gniees dnA
.etal oot emoc dah krab gninraw s’floW tub
~ .llits resolc ,sdneirf esolC
,mih fo tnorf ni retsnom redips cihcysp gnitfihsepahs emos saw ti fi neve rO
.rehtie em ot esnes yna ekam t’nseod tI .wonk I“
,mih fo pot no ylivaeh dednal xof eht dna
.mih llemS .mih guH
.ylrae oot pu dna etal oot tuo neeb d’eh
.won syad wef a rof taht gniod neeb d’eH
”?depleh snoitop eht …mU“ ”.haeY“
.muidet fo tniop eht ot detaeper hturt a ylno eb yam
?thgir ,mih llet ot evah I
.weiv otni renroc eht denrut ti sa
.dneirf taerg a hcus si nrohT
,seye dna eson sih gnuts lohocla ehT
”,detcartsid tib a kool uoY
.neeb reve d’eh esle erehwyreve fo draehnu erew srewohs mraW
,tfahs s’raeb eht dehcuot dna pu dehcaer wap
rethgit decarbme yeht
”seoF dna sdneirF fO“
.gnikaerb eson s’nilbog eht fo hcnurc gniyfsitas eht tlef eH
.lleps thgiS gnidnuorruS sih otni ygrene ihc delennahc eh sa
.detcilfnoc siht eb dluohs rykeS yhw tuo erugif t’ndluoc eh tub
,ecno ta seciov tnereffid rieht htiw gnimaercs ,snoitome eht fo llA
,detrats eh ,yletacileD ?won trats yhW
?mih dlot I fi ,thguoht eh
.tuo pleh dluoc stseug sih yllufepoh erehw
nrohT ,taht ekil ot smees eH
nac uoy dna ,ereh eb ot dalg tsuj yllaer s’ohw
!evael annog s’eh ,pihsdneirf doog a gniniur
?raeb siht evol nrohT diD
,yltnatsnoc mih htiw gniyalp nrohT tnuoc uoy sselnU
nac uoY .rohtuA eht yb uoy rof daer
.dehcterts ecnelis ehT
,riovreser eht morf drawpu retaw eht ecrof ot enO
.gniht fo tros taht otni erew gnihctaw enoyna fi
,pmur elbazis dna ,sgel ,kcab sih ot no devom eh nehT
”.ti dekil uoy llet nac I ,haeY .hO“ ”.gniht rewohs eht
.oga syad elpuoc a ti dezilaer I“
?uoy htiw gnorw si lleh eht tahw
,tcejbo eht elcricne dna retne lliw ygrene eht woh pam ot evah uoy
tub… .yad yreve regnorts gnitteg neeb ev’yeht hguoht
,cinut s’xof eht hguorht ecils ot deganam efink dnah-ffo eht tub
,ylevitatnet tsrif ,derolpxe
.tsaf ,mih no gnisolc erew yeht taht saw ot noitnetta gniyap saw eh tahW
.snoitpo rehto yna evah yllaer t’ndid raeb eht dna xof eht tuB
.yawa og thgim ti thguoht I dnA
,ti retfa delley nrohT ”!TUO YATS DNA“
.aedi na tog xof ehT
.pu gnilbbub egar desnes eh mih revo dehsalps ti sa dna
,hu ,eht rof sknaht osla dnA“
.tib elttil a yb ,oot retrohS
.bmun tnew niks siH
,mih htiw evol ni m’I rednow on s’tI
”.doog hO“ ”.haeY“ ,dias nrohT
.noitcere demahsa-regnol-on s’raeb eht otno gnidacsac
.delworg eh ”,ydaer m’I“
,kcil regnol a nehT
,daeh sih evoba deraeppa seye neerg gniwolg xiS
,tem shtuom rieht dna ni denael eH .erom dedeen
.hguoht ,gnikool driew erew yehT
.oot pu mih gnipleh dna wap gnorts tey elppus s’xof eht gnibbarg
”.huh ,ssenkciuq fo snoitoP“
,syad fo elpuoc tsap eht rof dnA
.stonk otni hcamots sih detsiwt xof emosdnah siht htiw syaw gnitrap fo thguoht eht tsuJ
.demlehwrevo saw rykeS
.dekrow ti woh wenk fo dnik eh os
.tuo ti erugif t’ndluoc eh yhw dnatsrednu t’ndluoc rykeS
.htuom sih morf slaiv noitop neerg-hsiulb owt gnippord
dna seye sih deworran eH  .rof drah yrev deniart ylraelc eh taht scep fo tes a pu gnirevoc etiuq ton ,llew
.tserof eht drawot nar dna tsiaw sih dnuora lewot sih denetsaf ylkciuq rykeS
.dessefnoc evol ,delaever evoL
.gninraey dna ssensuovren fo xim a gniees
?hcum os pu mih ezorf taht seye neerg peed s’nrohT otni gnikool tuoba ti saw tahw oS
.flesmih edisni peed kool ot decrof saw dna
,reggad a gnitcelfed dna gniws ratimics a rednu gnikcuD
,gnillaf sevael eht gnomA
,dehcatta saw mra lacinahcem sih erehw ,redluohs tfel siH
?eb ti dluoc tluciffid woH
.rehto eht morf dluoc eh sa pmuj a fo hcum sa gnivig elihw gel thguac eht no thgiew sih gnittup
.delevram nrohT .depsag rykeS
.raluguj s’raeb eht ot ekirts reggad a gnimim tfel sih dna
.lausunu s’tahT .romra tsehc rehtael rieht dniheb morf gnimoc wolg hsilprup a dah lla yehT
ehcilc a taht rebmemer ot llew si ti tub ,ehcilc a sa
.shtnom wef tsap eseht revo dewohs nrohT erac eht lla derebmemer rykeS
.derrulb noisiv siH
,egdol s’esnohplA drawot kcab nar dna denrut tsuj eH
.mih htiw ylwols dehtaerb nrohT sa demlac yllautneve shtaerb deggar ,kciuq s’rykeS
.tserof eht morf gniohce sgnab duol owt yb detpurretni saw eh
,ruf s’raeb sih gnola swap sih nar dna kcab dellup nrohT
,ti detavitca taht enur eht dehcuot
.sdik dna efiw a evah dna nwod elttes yllautneve thgim eh woh ecno denoitnem dah nrohT tuB
.sesucxe erom on dah dah raeb eht os
,siht rof uoy etah annog s’eH
.raf os ecitnerppa doog a neeb s’eH
.etats siht ni ton yllaicepse
,esion htiw zzub ot deunitnoc dnim s’rykeS
wor a ni sehcnup eerht ,owt ,enO
.gnikahs erew sdnah siH
.raeb cinotatac eht gnidloh tsuj ,tnelis llef yllanif xof
.larroc esroh desusid eht fo trid dekcap eht otni swalc sih gniggid
.ecnats elbats ,ediw a otni teef dewalc sih deppets dna delahni eh sa slirtson enisru s’rykeS gnignits ,ria eht ni gnignah llits saw wed gninrom ehT
.wap s’raeb sih dloh ot dehcaer nrohT
.gel s’raeb eht drawot raeps sih gnibbaj
ezilaer ot desirprus etiuq saw raeb ehT
.ffo gniylf strap latem fo stnemgarf htiw
trohs tuc saw noitamalcxe suoirotciv s’nrohT ”-ols ooT“
.nepo saw ig sih fo tnorf eht deciton eh sa ezag sih dewollof raeb ehT
,seot sih neewteb dekrow lios dloc ehT
sgnidaelp eltneg s’xof sih raeh t’ndluoc eH
.flesmih ot thguoht eh ,trela yatS
.dezigolopa raeb eht ”,yrroS !tihs hO“
,emoh raen saw eh ylikcuL
.gnimit lufwa ,delaever terceS
.ysmulc oot erew sdnah tuB
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.sgniht wen gniyrt tuoba yraw hcum t’nsaw eh tuB
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.flesmih htiw detnioppasid
,seye neerg s’xof eht fo hsalf eht nI
.romra rieht gnibbarg dna gnicreip swalc sih
) taht wonk dluohs I ,hteet on hteet on ,tihs hO
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.gnipip reppoc fo stnemges detnahcne eht denimaxe tsrif d’eh sa noitanicsaf eht derebmemer eH
thgiew nwo sih fo tsom hctac ot deganam
.ylkciuq os gniht pihsnoitaler elohw eht no ni lla og ot nrohT gnitcepxe t’nsaw eH
.mih ni tnemeticxe fo egrahc a gnitingi
.tsehc sih ni ygrene fo egrus a tlef rykeS
”–m’I kniht I ,nrohT“
,mih rof llams oot owt ro ezis a ebyam
.ecaf s’rykeS ssorca gnillor htaerb sih fo gof eht
,knis eht rof elbat gninid eht tsap thgiarts gnidaeh
.stnemragrednu – nwo neve ro – raew ot ton noisiced sih gnisruc yltnelis
.ti wohs ot yaw rehtona saw siht dna
.taht otni eb dluoc enoemos ebyam sseug I
.sesnes sih lla tuo denword taht gnizzub a htiw dellif niarb siH
,flesmih hctac ot deganam xof deppirt ehT
,mra thgir gnol ylhsikaerf a dah deciton eh meht fo enO
.nepo edis tfel sih gnivael ,dekcolb dna ti was xof ehT
,efil sih fo emit tseb eht neeb dah shtnom wef tsap eseht dna
,ylleb s’rykeS nwod gninnur retaw eht was eh dna
.t’nerew yltnerappa snilbog ehT
evitatnet A .keehc s’xof eht desserac yltneg rykeS
,tserof eht drawot dekool dna dehguoc tsuj eh dna ,esuap A
.tnemesuma sih dih ylkciuq nrohT
”.tihs ,hO“ ,dias nrohT
.noisnet sih desae retaw mraw eht sa hgis eguh a tuo tel rykeS
,tfel ytnelp llits saw ereht tub
.hcum oot tsuj saw tI
srae sih dekrep nrohT yriw eht
.elttab fo taeh eht ni nettogrof ,tniop emos ta ffo nellaf dah lewot siH
.hguoht ekawa yats attoG
,yaw doog yllaer A
.taht dekil flesmih eh hcum woh gniwonk
.pihsdneirf rieht ot od dluow noitazilaer dnuofwen sih tahw fo diarfa yrev saw rykeS
.zzuf niarb eht hguorht deretlif ylwols sdrow s’nrohT
.ylkciuq oot devom ti niaga tub
”won efas er’uoY“
llor a otni ydob eliga ,ehtil sih gnidlof
,snilbog rof tuo hctaw dna egdol eht ta yats ot oud eht deksa d’eH
.dluoc eh fi ,tsrif nwodtuhs eht morf kcab mih gnirb ot dedeen nrohT
saw tuo gnitrulb emac tahw tuB ”.wonk t’nod I“
syawla si ereht taht
.niaga tnorf eht ot dnuora delcric dna
,ylleb dnuor s’raeb eht ot pals lufyalp a htiw
.sregnif elpuoc a deruoP
,oot tib elttil a sllab sih deldnof dna pu dehcaer eH
.ti draehsim d’eh niatrec ,desufnoc
.ediw smra sih daerps rykeS  ”?yddub ,ydaer uoY“
”?taht si kceh eht tahW“
,sresuort dna cinut sih ni tsuj llits dna sselnopaew ,nrohT
,tnemtnahcne na gnitavitca elbuort emos gnivah neeb dah rykeS
,lamron ot kcab og nac sgniht dna edaf lliw sgnileef eht ebyam rO
,kcen s’nrohT ta thgir saw tuons
.rohtuA eht yb daeR  .sevlesruo ot
.nrohT ,uoy htiw evol ni m’I
mih fo erom dnif
,ylpeed ,mih tuoba derac eH
.mih gnisahc ,stnuom drazil rieht gnidir snilbog fo elggag a ees ot kcab dekool dna
,sgel sih neewteb derewol liat siH
,tnemom tsal eht ta tfel eht ot yawa ekorb dna dekcud nrohT
.gniniart gninrom emos gniod sdneirf fo elpuoc a ekil kool tsuj dluow siht – enola erew yeht
…ton er’uoy …er’ew
.evom tsrif eht ekam ot rykeS rof detiaw nrohT ,emit sihT
– dellac eh ”!retsaf ,xO“
.tas yeht sa delims raeb ehT
.hcuot mraw s’rehto hcae gnirovas dna esolc rehto hcae gnidloh
.rehtegot sruoh dna sruoh gnidnepS
.nepo eht ni tuo ti teg ot emit saw ti ,on tuB
detcennoc dna edis sih ot kcik a demia rykeS
- rekcatta nwo sih dah nrohT
,tsiom elttil a llits ruf ,tas owt ehT
.denethgit ssalg eht no pirg siH
”.driew gnieb saw I nehw nevE
.ho — yllaer yllaeR
”.thgif riaf a eb ton thgiM“
.tsehc dna smra s’rykeS htiw detrats eH
.raeb eht morf raeh ot gnitcepxe saw nrohT tahw ton saw sihT ”.uoy ssik …dnA
.sretsnom ynam woh swonk ohw ffo thgif dna
,knis eht evoba flehs eht ta pu dekool rykeS
.hsub a no hcnum ot gnitrats meht fo eno
.dnuos detcepxenu eht ta depmuj rykeS
~ .dnim ot mees t’ndid xof eht tuB
”?detcartsid ton er’uoy erus uoy ,yddub ,hU“
,sekirts efink owt tcelfed ot thgir dna tfel gniylf
.pu doots eh sa edis eht ot mih fo ffo nrohT dehsup rykeS
emoc tsum taht tuo gnimoc eno si ereht dnA .nwo ruo
,tsrif ekirts ot detpmetta rykeS degdod dah taht nilbog ehT
,tnemom a tsuj rof mih gniliaf gniniart knom sih
,tsehc sti ot kcik dilos a detnalp eH
.mih fo tuo deniard ygrene s’noitop eht fo tsal eht sa nwod dna pu gnipmuj
.mih fo tnorf ni gnidnats raeb gib siht ot trap llams on ni sknaht
.sih fo seye esohT .gnizama os
sa thgilnus gninromdim eht thguac mucerp fo pord A
.nikserof nworb krad eht fo tuo dekeep daeh hsiknip ehT
revo gnitlit ylraen nogaw s’esnohplA dettops dna revo dekool riap ehT
?yawa mih hsup ti lliw ,mih llet I fi tub
,pu doots regdab ehT
raor lamirp ,peed a tuo tel eH
,xO saw eman sti ,sey
.esnes yna ekam t’nseod sihT
.mih revo nar retaw eht sa knis eht ni daeh sih gnuh eH
,raeb fo tnecs eht htiw dexim etsat ytlas fo tsrub ehT
,thgir sleef ti …siht tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.truh ot hguone peed gniknis
.htaerb a koot eh sa ihc sih gnidnuorg
.nur a ta ffo koot eH
.esirprus rettu fo kool sih ta delims dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dias rykeS ”,nrohT ,sknahT“
.ykSeulB dna yrruFoS no
.delims eh ”?txen s’ohW“
,wol nwod saw nrohT
.elbissop sa noos sa taht fo erac ekat ot dedeen eH
,drows trohs nelots sih htiw ekirts efink tsrif eht deirrap eh
.flesmih ot erows rykeS !tihs ,tihs ,tihS .nar eh sa
”…tsuj er’ew dnA …ton m’I
”.semit dnasuoht a siht enod ev’ew ,evlas gnilaeh tsuj s’tI“
.gninrom yreve tsomla od ew ekil
”.daer ev’I tahw tsael ta ,yllautneve ti rof leef a teg uoy tuB
thguartsid ehT .”yrros m’I“ dna ”yako s’tI“ dna
.ecaf s’nilbog eht ot yltcerid thgir sih htiw gnihcnup
.lewot sih gnirb ot nettogrof d’eh ,parc dnA
.meht dednuorrus snilbog gniniamer xis eht sa kcab ot kcab devom nrohT dna rykeS
.tuo dellihc sgnileef eht elihw no sucof dluoc eh taht ti ot thgiew lanoitome na tuohtiw gnihtemoS
.rehtegot tneps ev’ew emit siht lla mih gnilgo
.rewop war fo evaw a ni enips sih nwod dna pu gniwolf
,egdol eht ot rood eht nepo werht eH
.)gniniart tsuj erew yeht ecnis ,esruoc fo yltfos(
.htuom sih fo tuo gnillips detrats sdrow eht
,noitacifitsuj emos htiw ,fo thguoht eb yam yrots tuo gnimoc ehT
.slairetam s’ereht …tsriF“
.tsael ta won thgir toN
…tuB“ ,deremmats nrohT
s’rykeS  .nwod tnew srae sih dna
,deeps pot naht retsaf gninnur saw xo lacinahcem ehT
.ot desu eh sa tsaf sa etiuq evom t’ndid eh dnA
.yako eb d’eh mih llet oT
.yawrood nepo eht morf dellac eciov s’nrohT
.thgir sih htiw semit fo elpuoc a gnibbaj
.ytic eht ot daor eht no meht was eh semitemos dna
,depsag ylneddus raeb ehT - tiaW
.niaga gnimlehwrevo gnitteg saw tI
,kcab sih no drah dednal raeb gib ehT
,sevac knuleps ,segalliv lacol dnefed ot sboj ddo gniod neeb d’yehT
,gnitalp latem sti fo emos gnissim llits saw tI
?yug gib yako uoY“
,ssentew dna htmraw s’rehto hcae tlef yeht sa neht
.ylreporp tuo denaelc saw eno hcae erus gnikam dna seirujni rof gnikcehc
,ti tuoba gnikniht ,lleW
.thgin retfa thgin ot txen peelsa gnillaf ot desu nettog d’eh ksum gnitrofmoc eht
.hcaer t’ndluoc eh erehw tops etirovaf sih ni ,kcab s’rykeS dehctarcs nrohT
.tcepxe ot tahw aedi on dah dah eH
– rof gnikool saw eh noitulos eht tsuj ton saw dnuof eh tahW
,esolc siht eno nees reven d’eH
,dehsalf drows trohs deworrob s’nrohT
.gnab-gnab deriap duol a htiw meht koohs dna seert eht otni dekaerts sbro eulb ynit owt ehT
,daeh sih koohs eH
.seilppus yub ot thgin suoiverp eht tuo dedaeh dah esnohplA dnA
”.ysae ,syug elttil eseht fo erac ekat ot elba neeb evah dluohs esnohplA“
.sdnuow s’rehto hcae ot evlas gnilaeh gniylppa
.doog sleef tI .thguoht eh
.cigam ruoy htiw ti gnirewop si pets tsal ehT“
,dewollah dnuorg ,tneb seenK
,tfel sih htiw kcatta raeps gnimocni s’nilbog eht detcelfed eh ,gninnirG
,desaeler ihc siH
,erofeb kcid dekcus reven dah eH
.ti deffins dna tuo kroc eht deppop eH
.htrof dna kcab gnimmiws sthguoht demrof-flah
.mih fo pot no yltcerid dnal dluow raeb eht tnaem hcihw
.kool resolc a teg ot ti desu dna elconom enacra sih derewol eH
.derettahs dna dekcarc ssalg ehT
.ti gnippirg dna dnuora gnipparw
.seye sih deworran raeb derruf-nworb ehT
.yponac tserof eht hguorht gnicra snilbog deye-ediw eht delleporp thgil etihw-neerg thgirb fo smaeb owt dna
”.ti tcartta taht munimula ekil seno cificeps dna
.llew sa wef a naht erom gnikat tub
.elttil a dekoms dna derrihw nonnac ehT .pu dekool yllanif regdab ehT ”.haey ,hU“
tub – lareneg ni gniklat tsuj ,meht otni eb nac elpoep emos ,naem I
,dias
.ti denimaxe dna wap thgir s’rykeS debbarg yltneg nrohT
,tsehc s’rykeS ssorca mra thgir sih
.rehtruf derolpxe seugnot rieht dna
,meht detfil eh sa smlap sih otni ygrene sih delennahc dna
,kcil a htiw detrats eH
traeh sih ni gnap a htiw deton nrohT dna
.kciuq thgir ffo meht deracs slleps yhsalf wef a ,esolc oot tog reve yeht fi tuB
.no gniog saw tahw tuo erugif ot emit dah snilbog eht erofeb ,tnew snoitop eht nwod oS
.tceffe derised eht sah dna ,flesti no ni gnipparw
.elahni yreve htiw tnecs ysdoow s’xof eht llems dluoc eh dna
~ .niaga dellac eh ”!xO ,retsaF“
.siht ekil demlehwrevo tog semitemos rykeS
.ypeels tib a seye regdab dlo derit s’esnohplA ekam ot detrats dah sdnuos cimhtyhr ehT
.eugnot s’nrohT no gnibborht dna gnipmuj detrats kcoc siH
.stnemom fo tsefeirb eht rof gniteem seye rieht
,pu gniklaw xof eht was eh naht taht ezilaer raeb eht did renoos oN
”…hu ,ot em tnaw uoy oD .tol A .did I“
,mih dleh tsuj nrohT sa mih dnuora smra sih leef ro
”.esneffo yna ekat t’nod I wonk ot uoy tnaw I tub ,dessarrabme er’uoy yhw wonk t’nod I
.oot tceffe gnikat saw noitop s’rykeS sa
.seye gnidaelp tub demahsa s’raeb eht otni dekool xof ehT
.niap htiw dehsalf dnuow tsehc sih sa decniw xof eht dna
,mih revo dehsaw taht gnilgnit eht dna etsat ekil-hsidaresroh eht dezingocer nrohT
.meht no s’X eht htiw selttob fo wor eht ta
.hguoht hctaw ot nuF
.deciton xof eht ,taebtraeh sih htiw nwod dna pu gnicnuob saw tI
,esnetni erom tog gnihctarcs eht sA
– erofeb neppah siht nees dah nrohT
”seoF dna sdneirF fO“   yojne esaelP
,dnuora denrut nrohT ”.uoy evol I“
,ylideeps yrev ,dias nrohT
.sworg noissap ,sknirhs raeF
.mih etavitcaer ot elba neeb dah esnohplA ees ot gninetraeh saw ti tub
yllaer eW“ .ytsedom fo esnes dnuofwen yltnerappa s’raeb eht ot evitisnes eb ot gniyrt
,deredisnoc sgniht lla ,enif tsuj saw hcihW
,denrut raeb eht dna xof ehT
.hcum taht em rof erac ot demees reve eno on ,mih erofeB
,sedolpxe ylbissop ro tuo selzzif tnemtnahcne eht neht ,gnorw ti od uoy fI
.sregnif sih hguorht deppihw liat tfos yllufthgiled s’xof gnilbmut eht sa ria fo luftsif a tog ylno rykeS tub
,detreva seye sih tpek nrohT
,tnuom sih fo ffo nilbog tsrif eht denilsehtolc nrohT
.nwodtuhs lluf a deretne eh sa denekcals ecaf siH
,tnemevom daeh kciuq eht htiw gnippolf srae yzzuf-os-ho ,gib sih
rykeS ”?enog snilbog ,hu ,ehT“
.esnohplA ta dekool raeb eht dna xof ehT
.ecnelis eht dnats t’ndluoc raeb dekan gib ehT
,stsehc rieht ni thgir snilbog eht fo owt kcurts dna drawrof deppets eh
.flesmih deksa eh ?radec taht saW
”,sseug I ,ecitcarp fo tuo tib a tsuj ,hu ,m’I“
,ekil neeb ev’I gniknihT .dam rO
,seye s’raeb sih ta pu dekool eH
.wolf ihc sih gnikcolb saw gnihtemos tub
.dluoc ti sa tsaf sa gnipollag detrats tsaeb latem gib eht dna
,cigam reted taht ,etihparg ekil ,sdnuopmoc cificeps era erehT .detnahcne eb nac tcejbo yna tsuj toN
,eno yb eno tuo sgnileef sih esaet gnipleh yb ffo ti daeh yllausu nac eh denrael dah xof ehT
,deeps erutangis sih htiw raeb eht drawot dehsad xof ehT
,epaga htuom sih htiw gnidnats
,rewohs eht ot kcab deklaw rykeS dna nrohT sA
.gniladepkcab deredisnoc eH .tihs ,lleW ”?tahW“
.lufrednow tlef rewohs roodtuo ehT
.mih fo edisni morf gninihs erew retniw krad a retfa enihsnus fo syar tsrif eht ekil ,mraw tlef eH
”.tcejbo yreve rof emas eht si ssecorp eht esuaceb ykcirt sa ton s’trap tahT
.reve naht noitceffa erom tlef ylno eh
”.uoy llet ot dah I tuB
elbapacni si hcihw
.nrohT htiw ssenisub dehsinifnu eht ylbaborP
.gniniatsus-fles ygrene eht peek ot dna
.dnim ot mees t’ndid xof eht tuB
.rehtegot gnirutnevda shtnom wef tsap eht revo xof siht htiw evol ni nellaf ylwols d’eh
~ ”.uoy llet ot gnihtemos evah I ,nrohT“
,mih barg ot ydaer tog rykeS hguoht dna
.nwod gniwols emit fo hsuh neddus eht dna
,swolf retaw ,dloh sdnaH
,flesmih ot thguoht eh ,gninrom llits s’tI ?detsuahxe os leef I od yhW
– serutaerc fo gnisaelp yllacitehtsea tsom eht ylirassecen t’nera snilbog ,woN
.rentrap gniniart sih detseb d’eh yppah ylraelc
…tsuj s’eh ,dneirf ruoy tsuj s’eh ,dneirf ruoy tsuj s’eH
,ylevitatnet ,dias nrohT
.detavitcaed ,hcneb s’nogaw eht no nwod llef eh dna
.dennirg dna nwod dekool xof ehT
.htuom sih ni rettib saw tI
.seye neerg lufituaeb sih htiw ecaf s’rykeS dehcraes eH
,elpparg sdneirf ,sesir nuS
dah rykeS .raeb fo sdnuop derdnuh wef a rednu dnuorg eht tih eh sa demialcxe xof eht ”!foO“
.tsaf ylgnisirprus saw ekirts s’nilbog eht tub ,kcolb ot devom rykeS
,xof sih ta revo akdov gnippird eht hguorht dereep raeb ehT
,rykeS fo dnof ylniatrec saw nrohT
.sucof reraelc otni emac seiromem eht ,ecnatsid elttil a htiW
,decnavda raeb ehT
rebmemer ot llew osla si tI
,egrahc rieht dezinorhcnys yeht sa tem seye s’nrohT dna rykeS
.drazil sih fo ffo gnipmuj yb evohs s’rykeS degdod ylworran nilbog dnoces ehT
,seirraH nomoloS yb
.daeh s’nrohT drawot thgir sih htiw hcnup a demia dna ,tfel detnief
.detrats raeb eht dna
.deksa nrohT ”?hctaw peek uoy naC
.elbissop thguoht reve d’eh naht retsaf raf eslupmi yreve ot gnidnopser ,hctiwt dna hcnelc selcsum sih tlef rykeS
dluow tahW .rentrap gnirutnevda sih ot dehcatta os teg ot tcepxe t’ndid yllaer eH
,ereht tas tsuj sdrazil gib ehT
.sesnefed sih rednu teg rekcatta sih deciton t’ndah eh ,eirever sih nI
.ekahs ot detrats waptoof s’rykeS
.emit eht lla mih htiw eb ot tnaw I .pu mih evig t’nac I
ti dezeeuqs nrohT
”.retaw emos teg ot deen I …I
deddon rykeS ,mih dniheB
,raeb tuots eht naht rellat toof a gnidnats ,mih morf ssorcA
deyortsed ro deretla eb t’nac ti taht os ti gnilaes si pets tnemtnahcne tsal ehT“
”.suoregnad fo dnik s’ti
gnitalp rehtael s’floW otni knas sworra fo elpuoc a yletaidemmI
.traeh sih ni gninrub sgnileef eseht lla pots ot dedeen eH
,htaerb s’nrohT dellems rykeS
.pu denaelc siht teg ll’I“
,drah gnihtaerb saw nrohT
.nalp doog a ekil demees dah tI
,ti werdhtiw nilbog eht sa raeps eht ta debbarg dna niap fo raor a tuo tel raeb ehT
.taht htiw gnorw gnihtyna s’ereht taht toN .thguoht d’eh
.yllaer ,gnidnatstuo etiuQ
ekil sgniht gniyas
.mih pirt ot kcab gel sih detrad rykeS sa
,yaw elbissop yreve ni mih ot dekan yletelpmoc won
”!tsaf oot era syug esehT !kcuF“
,liat xof yhsub sih dehsiws dna
.ecno ta lla gnimaercs dna gninruhc erew sedisni sih ekil tlef tI
,tcafitra desruc a fo ffo secneuqes enur gnidaer ro
,erom desu evah dluow eh dna
.em rof serac eh yaw ehT
,gnihctaw saw enoyna taht ton
,thgirb dna raelc saw yks ehT .ylrae saw tI
”.uoy htiw tuo ti erugif ot tnaw I erus ytterp m’I tuB
,htaerb rieht thguac owt eht retfA
.yddub ,niaga em llet ,yeH“
,hgU .flow lacinahcem sih ot txen hcneb s’nogaw dlo eht no snier eht dleh ylesool eH
.llef eh sa drows trohs sih fo mih gnimrasid ylkciuq
.raef dna erac fo lluf seye esoht gniees
,rykeS dna nrohT revo dna snilbog eht fo eno fo sredluohs eht no depmuj floW
,rehto eht htiw snier eht dna wap eno htiw tah sih gnidloh saw esnohplA
.gninrom siht tnetsisrep neeb dah nrohT tuB
si yrots s’yadoT dna
snaom eht dna skeehc s’nrohT no denethgit swap s’raeb ehT
~ .gnileef doog a saw tI
,thguoht eh ,gnirraps tsuj erew eW
.seert eht otni gniylf nilbog eht tnes taht hsup ylleb a htiw drawrof deppop raeb gib ehT
.ni edils rebmem kciht s’raeb eht gnittel
.mih gnisol naht esrow eb d’taht ,taht od t’ndluoc I dnA
,pu doots eh sa dezigolopa ylkciuq rykeS ”!nrohT yrros ,hO“
.ruf nat sih htiw yldnik detsartnoc taht sresuort neerg esool dna cinut etihw detleb a gniraew
.ti tuoba thguoht neve reven dah
.ylgu fo esod artxe na evah ot demees snilbog eseht
,niaga mih barg dna yrt ot dnuora nups raeb eht sa
s’rykeS .niaga gnitnap erew owt ehT
,semit derdnuh a mih htiw deniart ev’uoY
.nonnac sih rof dopirt a pu tes ot nageb yldrawkwa dna
.erom yna ni ti dloh t’nac I tuB .lliw ti ebyaM
.erofeb mih rof deneppah t’ndah taht
.ti tuoba thguoht dna desuap nrohT
.demialcxe nrohT ”?!snilboG“
,elttab fo noitaralihxe eht ni gnilims htob
.esolc yrev nworg d’yeht dnA
.taht ekil daeh sih ni kcuts teg flesmih tel t’ndluohs eH
.nwod gnimoc retaw fo eguled eht no gnikohc
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,raeb sih rof erusaelp hcum os saw erehT
,dnim ot emac skoob morf deziromem d’eh serugif dna selbat fo snezod sa ylwols detrats esnopser s’raeb ehT
”?gnitnahcne ot spets eht era tahW
.did enoyreve tahw saw tahT
,yltnatsnoc nrohT ta gnikool rykeS deciton dah esnohplA
,tnenoppo sih htiw pu derauqs
,tuB .yag sa flesym fo thguoht reven I
?erofeb saw ti gnitacixotni woh deciton ton eh dah woH
:ehcilc ro muidet fo
.rehtegot neeb d’yeht shtnom eht ni ydob sih tuoba yhs neeb reven dah rykeS
.dluoc ti sa tsaf sa ffo nar dna lialf sti deppord nilbog tsal ehT
.noitacidni yna erew snaom s’rykeS fi
.retaw fo maerts eht rednu ylleb dna smra sih debbur eh sa snoitpo sih gniredisnoc detrats dna daeh sih koohs eH
.oot ti dekil eh dnif ot desirprus tib a saw eH
- deracs ,yrgna ,nwod saw eh emit yrevE
.taht rof ton ,oN“
,dluoc eh tseb sa pu derevoc ylkciuq eH
,tsael ta ,yrots tuo gnimoc eno
,tnemtnahcne eht fo smhtyhr tnadrocsid eht gnizinorhcnys ni
?yag …em ekam taht seoD
.snilbog eht fo eno gnikcart hcae
.senil yel larutan s’tcejbo na tuo pam ot ykcirt yllaer s’ti dna tcejbo eht fo epahs eht htiw seirav tI
ta deiduts d’eh yretsanom eht ot kcab og dluow eh ebyam thguoht dah rykeS
,liart eht fo htrae dekcap eht no dnuorg sleehw nogaw nedoow ehT
.ezeeuqs dekaos-ezoob gib a mih evag dna nwod dekool xof eht sa pu dekool raeb ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif
,nonnac enacra elbatrop ,lufrewop ,xelpmoc yrev a eb ot deraeppa tahw gnidloh esnohplA ees ot denrut htob yehT
,gel s’raeb eht fo og tel ot esnes eht evah t’ndid eh taht evom eht yb hguone desirprus saw xof ehT
.dehctiwt selcsum yvaeh siH
.sredluohs s’rykeS gnibbarg dna ni gninael yb mih deppots nrohT tuB  ”–I“ ,detrats eH
,kniht nrohT
”.oot uoy evol I“ ”?haeY“ ”?rykeS dnA“
,egruS kcabkconK kaew a ni ygrene ihc sih esu ot deganam rykeS
”–ton s’taht yeH .era uoy erehT“
,tcejbo eht dnuora sdniw ygrene eht ,thgir ti od uoy fI
.mih no ysae oot si xof ehT
.gel sih fo edis eht otni tuc raeps ehT
,mra tfel sih htiw gel eht dekooh dna nwod wap sih thguorb nrohT ,hguoht ,ni kcab toof sih gnirb dluoc eh erofeB
.snilbog tuoba deirrow oot neeb reven dah eH
.noitcere derevocnu s’raeb dekan gib eht ta yltcerid gnirats
,tnatsni na ni ekawa detloj esnohplA
.sdrazil gib gnidir snilbog demra fo rebmun a ees ot nogaw eht dniheb yltcerid htap eht otni gnippets
?evael eh dluoW ?dam eb eh dluoW
.tnaw I tahw wonk t’nod I
.yb dezzihw nogaw eht sa thgir mih morf ssorca pu tes rykeS dna
,egdol yawa-dekcut sih fo tsaehtuos eht ot tserof eht ni devil yeht ,eruS
,mih htiw floW evah did eH
.ruf sih fo tuo sdrahs ssalg llams dna akdov eht hsaw retaw eht tel eh sa seye sih desolc raeb ehT
”.uoy tuoba erac I wonk uoY .yddub ,emit ynA“
,nogaw gnicnuob-ylivaeh-won eht no ecnalab retteb ot
.ytilaer dneb ot gniog s’ti woh
.ecaf sih no yltcerid retaw looc eht dehsalps dna
,deunitnoc raeb ehT
.ni emac yeht sa skcatta erom yrrap dna egdod ot tseb sih gniod ,dias nrohT
.esuap gnol a koot rykeS ”?deneppah tahW
.mih no tas nrohT sa ylleb sih no gnisserp thgiew mraw s’xof eht leef dluoc rykeS
.flesmih derevoc dna dluoc eh sa tsaf sa lewot eht debbarg rykeS
.dneirf sih gnirehtob neeb dah tahw raeh ot regae saw xof ehT
,nwod srae ,wap ni lewot
,citonpyh neeb evah thgim kcurts dna degdod eh sa delggij dna thgiew sih devom raeb eht yaw ehT
.elbat eht ot txen riahc a otni deppolf dna ssalg a dna akdov eht debbarg eH
.pu denaelc teg og annog er’eW“
.mih trofmoc ot ,saw xof eht ereht
.elpmis reve si traeh eht fo rettam hcus on ,esruoc fO
,seirraH nomoloS yb ”seoF dna sdneirF fO“ saw sihT      ~
,desserdnu ,straeh owT
~ ”.ffo esnir og uoY
.oot deppord srae
,dna ylleb thgit ,egral a pu gnirevoc
.ni evid ot snosaer doog tub gnihton ees dluoc xof ehT
?radec htiw flesmih bur eh diD
.esnohplA ,rereknit regdab dlo eht htiw gnitnahcne fo seiduts ni daeh sih gniyrub dna gniniart yliad rieht gnippiks
.syadawon ysae ytterp eros tog ti
.t’nac yllaer uoy hcihW .thguoht eh
.tey detset-elttab neeb yllaer t’ndah eninac lacinahcem eht hguoht
,erom yna mih htiw niart t’ndluoc I ,t’nod I fI
.etuc eb d’tI .rehtegot teg dluohs yehT
.pu nar ti sa krab lacinahcem s’floW draeh yeht ,neht tsuJ
– suoitneterp fo dnik saw ti thguoht eh
.tuc llams a saw erehT
.enim naht rekciht hcum os s’ti ,woW
.morf emoc dah sworra eht desseug eh erehw drawot slleps tsruB noissucnoC elpuoc a ffo tnes regdab dlo ehT
,naelc wap derujni s’rykeS dekcil nrohT
,ig stra laitram sih ni depparw saw eH
.esle gnihtyna htiw pu emoc t’ndluoc eh ,dessarrabme os saw eH
,tuons s’raeb eht dekcil eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.t’nsaw ylniatrec esnohplA
,hU“ .hguoht ti htrow llits ylbaborP
,romra rehtael s’nilbog eht otni sekirts owt bats-bats neht
.hsalf a ni ti od dluoc eh
.reduol dna repeed tog
,dnuorg eht drawot cra noitom-wols sti ni sreggad deppord ’snilbog eht fo eno thguac nrohT
.oga syad wef a ereh devirra ew ecnis lla ta deklat t’nevah
.secalp ddo ni tuo gnikcits shtworg suoromut driew dah wef a dna
.gnidloh saw eh nopaew eht drawot daeh sih detlit eh sa ekoj ot deirt eh
ylleb sih tsniaga gnicnuob renob sih fo erawa yrev
.sgnileef yvaeh eht morf mih gnitcartsid
.gninefaed saw taht enihw dehctip-hgih elgnis a otni degrem ylkciuq
.tuo yaw sih thgif dluoc eh
”?yug gib ,dnim ruoy no s’tahW“ ,dednopser eH
tsehc s’nrohT ssorca nar swap s’rykeS
,hu ,sih ta nwod dekool rykeS - llew
,krims s’dneirf tseb sih fo espmilg eht
raor a delfits rykeS
,yag adnik smeeS
?em htiw no gniog si tahw ,kcuF
,htap eht fo htuom eht ta seert gib eht fo eno dniheb neddih dah
.ti dleh dna wap s’nrohT debbarg rykeS
noissap sih lla deitpme eh sa
.niaga pu derauqs yehT
.daehrewohs eht fo tuo dewolf ti erofeb thgir ti yfirup ot eno tsal eht dna ,ti mraw ot eno
,seman htiw ycnaf oot tog reven esnohplA
.dewollaws neht ,detsat eriseD
.noitcesdim eht dnuora yllaicepse
.hctorc s’nrohT ot derutseg rykeS
?rof epoh ot hcum oot taht sI
.hcaet dna retsam a emoceb yllautneve dna
.ydobyreve ot sneppah ti ,yug gib yeH“
tib elttil a dezeehw xof ehT
.tsehc sih ni tuc gnol a gnivael
.htiw revo ti teg llew sa yaM
.osrot sti fo tuo gnikcits sworra elpuoc a dah floW taht
,erofeb bojwolb a nettog d’eH
.taht htiw gnorw gnihtoN .eep ot dedeen tsuj ylbaborp eh - renob sih dnA
.sdnuow suoirav rieht morf gnipmil
,nrohT gnidiova neeb d’eh
,rehtegot kcab klaw ot detrats yeht sa dias nrohT
,rorroh sih ot dnA
.nrohT ta dekool rykeS yaw gnitod eht ssim thgim uoY
.elims yrw a ekorb nrohT
,yas ot tuoba saw rykeS
.ti eveileb t’ndluoc rykeS
.eciton t’ndluow xof eht revenehw
.knurt eert a otni thgir drawkcab gnilwarps ti gnidnes
,drawrof dehsup raeb ehT
:elbissop eb yam rehto yna erofeb
.detatiseh raeb ehT
.yalpsid no noitcere lluf sih
,noisiced eht edam d’eh naht renoos oN
,drawrof thgiew sih detfihs neht
.retteb yna gniraf t’nsaw rykeS
.yddub sih saw siht