,ezis ruo flah naht regral gnihtyna tnuh ot elba eb ot sevlow enol rof nommoc t’nsaw tI
.delrans I sa desiar selkcah
kcap a tuohtiw flow a taht yas yehT
.doog ”edisni pu llew
.tsael ta ,ereh gnivah htrow laem a yletinifeD .ezorf I dna
,htaehs ym no ssenikcits
,teef ym ta ti deppord flowrehtO eht
erofeb thgir dnA
,ereh llits saw eH
emag llams gnitnuh
,god.ecioveht ta
,yawa ecnatsid a deklaw ylpmis flowrehtO eht tub
,peels fo yoj eht ot yaw
,laudividni yletirps ,ylevil
.foereht kcal ro ,efil fo yaw
.retirw yranecrem flow a
.seilimaf htrib ruo morf
.elam ylevitcnitsid saw tnecs ehT
.esoprup tuohtiw si
taht fo lla dna yna teg ot etarepsed ,ffur sih
.segru dna serised ym ,stnaw ym desserper I oS
;gnol rof enol yats t’ndid yllacipyt sevlow enoL .yrogetac
.enog ydaerla saw revol ym dnif ot detnioppasid
”?uoy er’erehw oS
eht hguoht ,em ot derrucco taht gnihtemos t’nsaw tsuj tI
.tniop a ekam ot ffo srae ruoy wehc
.secalp rehto ni em gniffins detrats won dna
,kcab em deffins eH
gniyas fo yaw a fo dniK .xim eht ot skram tnecs nwo ym dda ot neht dna won yreve gnippots
a saw rehtegot derahs ew tahw fo rednimer a sa tfel saw taht llA
.noitanigami dnoyeb
,reve sa lufyalp dna gnivol sa
.secneirepxe nwo ruo rof srohpatem sa slamina fo sroivaheb dna ,stiart ,secneirepxe eht esu ot ytiliba eht si
em no doof revotfel yna evah t’ndid
.ti ta og a evah dluoc elam rehtona dna em dediced I
,flowrehtO eht nopu pu flesym dehctih I oS
,em ot emac doolb dna hself reed fo llems gnorts eht nehT
I tcaf eht etipsed ,esnopser ni htuom dna ecaf ym ta dekcil flowrehtO eht ,did I sa dnA
;devlovni slaudividni eht tuoba atad fo stol niatnoc sgnikram tnecS
.gnitsop da na ekil hcum
erutluc dna tra yrruf fo tnemele cisab tsom eht yas yehT  .egap
.htiw nrob saw I taht tcaf a
.rehsurC seboD yb detide ,enizagam yag.sevloW ni deraeppa ylsuoiverp dah kcaP
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,tnecs yb flowrehtO eht dewollof I  .tsael ta
gnivig wolgretfa eht fo ezah eht
,hcnuh reed a ekil tlems
tahw fo pmul elbaezis a dleh eh wam sih nI
,ni skcil leef a tog
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ot ecnailpmoc detnaw yeht ;sbuc evah ot tog ohw ot ecnailpmoc tnaw tsuj t’ndid riap gnideerb ehT
.erehwesle strevda gnikram tnecs gnitsop sreffo retteb hcum teg dluoc yeht dediced sevlow enol ,netfo ooT
reve gnihtyna naht
– nwod hcnuah eht deflow I .oga snosaes owt
.ekil-evissimbus lla gnieb dna nwod-srae ,selur eht lla dewollof ,nwod srae ym tpek ,enil eht deot elam agemo doog yna ekil ,I
sa dereggats reven eh ,thgiew ym etipsed dna
.ecin tlef tI  .eta
,nwo ruo llac ot yrotirret yna dah ew ekil t’nsaw tI
,drawrof gnippetS
,dias ev’I sA
.seihcrareih dna selur driew sah kcap ehT  .eno tuohtiw
.mih ta ffins ot ecnahc eht koot I
,em nopu yponac tserof eht hguorht gnikaerts syar ot gninrom txen eht ekowa I
,redneg emas eht fo eno fo revol a ,saw I ohw rof
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow s’isakiM
,denigami evah reven dluoc I
saw secnereferp hcus rof smret lacinhcet
,detnaw eh tahw mih evig dluoc I esuaceb ylpmis ton
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
ma I taht si ,won srettam taht lla esuaceb
,ecarbme lanrac ni su fo owt eht gnikcol tonk ym
,rehtegot erew ew
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
ro sroirepus sa toN .rehtona yb detnaw gnileef tub
.ot detnaw eh esuaceb ylpmis tub
detnaw yletinifed I tuB .em ot tnesba
.eugnot ym nopu doolb ytsat suoiciled
.dnuora t’nsi ahpla eht nehw ateB eht ebyam ,ahplA eht ot ylno netsil ot evah sagemO lla woh ekiL
.rehtegot efil a gnivah reve morf su tneverp ot
htmraw a em nihtiw gnidurtni revol ym fo tfahs eht
,em ot kcab sih denrut eh
.revir gnimocpu na ,ykcul m’I fi ro ,eugnot ym htiw ti fo erac koot I nehw yromem a naht erom gnihton eb noos dluow taht ssenikcits a
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
kcehc ot dediced I os
floWisakiM yb ”kcaP“   ,ni
ym dna ,neht dna ereht thgirf a em evag raen nmaD
.rehtona dekcuf reven tub
luos dna traeh ym deruop I
.erom saw ereht gnihsiw dna spil ym gnikcil
,ti fo llems eht ot resolc tog I sa dnA
,gnidnatsrednu lautum fo tcap a yb dnuob
,saw flowrehtO eht ereht dna denrut I
erom mih detnaw ,em erofeb flow lufyalp siht
.kcab ym fo tuo sehca eht dehcterts dna pu tog I
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.saw htuom sih revo werd eugnot sih erehw naelc woh was I nehw dootsrednu neht
.tnuh sih morf der kcen dna ecaf sih
tnecs ot desirprus saw I ,eert a fo edis eht no gnikram tnecs a dehcaorppa ylsuoituac I nehw oS
,”emosewA m’I“ ,”htlaeh doog nI“
,eloh gnitiaw taht sdrawot
,doog gnileef fo yoj eht tsuj ton
,detnuoc yletinifed siht dna
,eugnot emos htiw
dnoces eht ton yletinifed tub
,rehtona ni kcap ym dnuof yllanif
,”selur riap gnideerb ylno“ eht fo esuaceb dnA
.roolf tserof eht no ylizal gnittis
.ti tuoba srehto dnimer dna
I sa mrots dliw a gnilkcub liat dna spih
,kcirt a saw siht esac ni ,mih ta seye rebma ym deworran I
hsilkcit erew taht secalP
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
.elcric-lluf wam sih dnuora gnilriws eugnot sih ,em sdrawot daeh dekaerts-doolb sih gnirab
”.em nioj ot luos dednim-ekil rof gnikool ,efiL ni ylenoL“
dna gnillol eugnot
ym ni ecno tsuj taht ekil gnihtemos od tub ,os ro keew yreve ti ta tnew sevlesmeht yeht nehw detnemmoc esle enoyna ekil t’nsaw tI
ebyam ;nosaer on rof uoy thgif ot ylekil erom raF
.swen dab yllacipyt era selaM
dna mih ot pu deppets I
.slauqe sa tub ,sretteb
,floWisakiM yb ,”kcaP“
nwod eno desahc kcap dlo ym ecnis ton ,elihw a ni reed dah t’nevah I tub
rednaw ot evah dluow I thguoht I nehw deraeppa ohw eh
,efil elbaresim
,rehtona eno htiw dekcol deniamer ew sa
,floWisakiM yb ”kcaP“ saw sihT
htmraw a yb dewollof ysatsce fo sehctiwt ,skrej dna stnap
,su ta worht dluow daeha syad eht tahw ton wenk ew hguoht dna
.ti no pu uoy ekat ot dediced
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
hguoht ,dekram tnecs ylerar sevlow enoL
srettam ylimaF dnuoF taht yas yeht dnA
.enola efil eninac ym fo tser eht
,erofeb dekcuf neeb flesym tel d’I
,era yeht tahw rof meht tpecca ot gnilliw erew ohw skcap ;skcap rehto
?thgir tnemhsinup fo taerht emos tuohtiw agemO na gnieb s’tahw ,yeh ,tub ,deppin tog llitS
.kcap eht fo htgnerts eht si flow eht fo htgnerts eht yas yehT
,kcap eht fo tuo tsac ma I dna
traeh ruoy sekam“
,skeehc sih ta dekcil
eno siht piks esaelp
,rehto hcae delzzun dna dekcil eW
.yrotirret nwo rieht kees ot tfel ohw esoht ro ,kcap eht fo tuo tsac esoht rehtie era sevlow enol taht yas ynaM
evah I .enola regnol on saw I taht won wenk I dna
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
.em htiw yad eht ecaf ot ydaer
,egakcap elohw ehT
ruFikiW ro AF sih no
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.)yas t’ndid ro( dias yeht revetahw
,rehto eht dnatsrednu ot eno eht esu su tel oS
rieht ,ytirohtua rieht ot taerht a ,ylamona na sa did ew tahw was yehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
edisa gnikcilf liat
,”kcap ni ycnacav weN“
,desufnoc saw I tnemom a roF
noitcerid etisoppo eht ni tuo tsac revol ym htiw
ni sa dooG .doog…tlems eH
.niaga flow rehtona ot esolc eb ot osla tub ,tae ot gnihtemos tog I taht ecin tsuj toN
.mrots dliw a gniggaw liat
.doog rof pu mih evag
resolc dna resolc yaw ym derettot I
,enola dlrow eht derednaw I oS
,liat detfil htaeneb ssa thgit mraw ni kcid fo gnidils eht dna ,liat
flow a tub renroc eht dnuor emoc dluohs ohw
tsim fo sffuh dna srepmihw ruo
dna egassem ruoy deffins ,yeH“
,elihw siht lla neeb d’I erehw suoiruc tsuj saw flowrehtO eht emussa dluoc I
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.srebmun rieht ot gnirb dluoc yeht tahw dna
”.ffO kcuF“ nommoc oot lla eht sa llew sa
,decnavda I sa eloh thgit mraw taht otni flesti dnuof kcid yM .detsurht
ekil noitamrofnI
,thgin krad dloc eht gnillif
.em ta srae dna daeh sih detnac ylerem flowrehtO eht tuB
.liat thgirpu na naht reffits em edam dna
noitcejer fo ecneirepxe eht evah su fo ynam os esuaceb
.t’nac tser eht elihw
.edis ym tsniaga ruf mraw fo sserp eht tlef dnA
,em erofeb duts siht otni
,rettam t’nseod yas t’nod ro yas yeht tahW
,efil ym fo ecneirepxe tseb eht saw tI
denioj dna tnew yeht
,detnap dna delrans ,deffuh I sa dnA
tsomla I ,gnikool fo yad-flah a retfA
.erew ew ohw gnieb ylpmis dna
.tuo dekcik llits erew elam eht dna I taht ni ,driew erew selur eht
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.flesti efil sa dlo sa mhtyhr a ni kcab dna drawrof devom I sa yllaudarg gnillews
.esruoc fo ,ssip a ekat ot dedeen llits ew
,erom gnihtemos ot edulerp a tsurht hcae
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,noisserpxe eht nodrap
,tsrif eht fo eb yam I
elpoep QTBGL ot
.ssa erab sih wohs ot
tsuj I revetahw etatigruger ot em detcepxe eh sselnu ton—
em tpecca dluow enon wenk I
htiw delgnim erusaelp fo gnillif a
,em sdrawot edorts flowrehtO eht nehT
.enola slaem regral tnuh ot noitibma dna ytiliba eht evah t’ndid I esuaceb noirrac dna
,renaelc tahwemos gnikool flowrehtO eht ,enod saw I nehW
a detseggus tnecs siht tuB
,kcuf nac riap gnideerb eht ylno woh ekiL
.tuo em tsac kcap ym sevlesmeht dellac ohw seno eht ecnis
.swaj sih ni doolb htiw
rehtona eno ta gnilzzun yllufyalp ,dnuorg eht ot depmuls ew sa dnA