.deggurhs tsuj emiaJ tub
.wols dna ecin nwod tnew eh oS
.spil rieht no selims tfos dah emiaJ dna haeL
peek‘ ,em rof derepmihw tsuj eh tub
.rewohs eht ni em rof pu denaelc teg dna og mih tel I tub
spih sih otno nwod gnimmals yllaer
.daeh reh ot denettalf srae s’god eht
.em sevol eh hcum woh em gnillet tpek tsuj eh dna
,llew ,thgirlA“
.dab ytterp saw noisserped sih tub
,ereht mih was dna moordeb eht otni tog I
.emit eht lla srentrap ym htob dnuora kcuts gnieb
.eilloC deveirgga
.niaga mih edir ot detrats I dna gniog peek dluoc ew mih dlot I oS“
.pots ot dah ew dna
s’JA revo lla emac I erofeb gniod saw I tahw ezilaer neve t’ndid I dna doog dna mraw dna ecin os tsuj saw tI
,deirt eh emit yreve tuB
gnihcterts tonk sih
dias eh yaw eht tub
.rehtnap emit-lluf dna ,retirw emit-trap a s’ohw
.176 ,pu
.no dehsup ehs os ,sdaeh rieht deddon owt ehT
.em dessik ehs dna
yltnecer nrop yag ta gnikool neeb d’eh taht em ot dettimda flow ehT
.niaga tuo em gnihcterts yllaer dna em revo mih fo gnikniht no denrut teg ot detrats dna gninaom mih draeh I
!mih fo lortnoc gnikat fo ecnahc yna evah I ekil gnilworg dna
,ni ti ebur yllaer ot detrats dna ebul eht tog I“
.oot suoiruc elttil a gnileef saw eh tuo snrut
.tuo ebul eht dna lewot a tog eh elihw gnippirts detrats I oS .mih detnaw I
,hcum taht pu debul gnieb tuoba yrrow ot deen t’nseod ehs eram a gnieb sseug I
.taht retfa tuokrow specirt ecin a flesmih gnivig yllaer saw yug roop eht dna kcoc sih nwod flesym knus I
,dias einnA ”,haey ,ma I“
.thgin taht enim saw ssa sih esuaceb
”,tuls a hcus er’uoY“
.gnikool er’ew tuB .tey toN“
ffo em tog dna em deregnif eH
,mih edor dna dnuora delggiw tsuj I
.em ssik ot detrats aruaL dna luferac dna ecin saw eH
sdrapoel dna shateehc neewteb ecnereffid eht gninialpxe dna krow yrruf gnitirw neeb s’eH
,dias tac eht ”,yrots eht uoy wohs tsuj nac I nehw yrots a uoy llet ot deen t’nod I“
,taht ekil gnihtyna ro sppa pukooh ta dekool reven I
.no gniog saw tahw mih llet dna mih ssik ot nwod nael ot dah I
.taorht reh deraelc einnA
!draehrevo eb d’ehs esirprus on s’ti
”,siht rof kcab uoy teg annog-G“
,elbatrofmoc erom teg ot kcab denael haeL dna emiaJ
.delggig ehS ”!yakO .woW
dah evah dluohs I ydob eht saw wenk I tahw si sihT
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,depmuj tsomla eH
niaga sdneirf reh ees ot doog os saw tI
,etoyoC triD yb daer
”.seirots elpuoc a raeh ot tnaw I ,ralloc ruoy teg ot deticxe os er’uoY
.seye reh ni gnillaf riah ,daeh reh fo don a htiw dias emiaJ ”,haeY“
,tsuj saw I ekil tlef I .elohw tlef I“
,yug teews a ekil demees syawla eH“
.esirprus ni pmuj eilloc eht edam wodniw eht no pat A
.meht rof dehca d’ehs
.gnorw gnihtemos did eh taht deirrow dna etuc lla tog JA dna yrc ot detrats I .esnetni
.laer si sihT !doG hO
.reh ta gnirats erew sdneirf reh
.ti pleh t’ndluoc I dna tilc ym bur dna selppin ym htiw yot ot strats aruaL dna ,em otni gnikcub si JA
”?yot eht teg uoy did erehW“
,taht ekil deldnahnam yllaer teg ot yppah os saw eH
.gnikcilf rae s’tac eht ,dennirg emiaJ ”!hooO“ .dias ehs
.seitnap ym otni nwod edils wap sih tel eh tuB“
,deggurhs tac eht
?gniteem ym erofeb semit owt ffo tog I kniht I
.ereh kcab emoc reven nac I ,laiciffo s’tI“
,drah dneirfyob ruo gnidir saw ehs tub
.rehtael xuaf eht tsniaga pu gnihsurb
setunim 51 ni gniteem a rof ydaer teg ot gniyrt saw I
gniggaw sliat rieht fo htob
.ta sdneirf reh tem syawla ehs htoob railimaf eht ot kert reh morf pu reh mraw ettal teews eht gnittel
,gnihtyna yas t’ndid einnA
.toh saw taht timda ot dah I neve ,’riS‘
.wap rehto reh ni setalp elpuoc a ekat ot gnitrats dna spuc s’enoyreve gnillifer ,eeffoc fo top a htiw yb emac ssertiaw ehT
.gel tnap a nwod ti detniop dna no-parts ym no tup I dna
saw tI .lewot eht detaoc
.gaw liat sih ees dna yob doog mih
.sregnif reh ni ylwols ti gninnips ,gat reh dnuof wap s’nooccar ehT
.elttil a detlem I dna ’ris sey‘
.sreh ni wap s’efiw reh gnikat ,dias ehs
eh dna em rof muc ot mih dlot
”…saw I .doog dna ylgnit os tlef tsuj I
meht htiw ereht efas yllaer tlef I
.gaw ot liat s’einnA esuac ecaf gnimaeb s’nooccar ehT
!etuc os denaom eH
em rof ydaer flesmih teg ot mih dedeen I mih dlot I“
.deb eht revo dneb ot mih llet I dna
”.oot taht htiw elggurts ew tub ,semit nuf eht tuoba klat syawla I wonk I“
”!snoitseuq esoht lla rewsna nac I dna ti llet em tel os eno siht yb deticxe ylraelc er’uoY“
,ereh tib a etiuq efil xes reh tuoba klat did ehs ,taht gnizilaer
,elbaroda ytterp saw tI
.emit yot emos gnivah saw nahtanoJ“
.em otni edils mih tel I
.yalpsid no saw gat depahs traeh a no retnuoc latigid eht litnu dnuora kcen reh no rekohc eht detsujda dna
.siht od nac I os serahs syawla einnA dna
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.rehtie eurt etiuq ton s’taht ,lleW“
,em ta kcab dekool eH
.uoy htiw taht erahs ot teg ot ecin saw tI“
.nwo reh no htoob éfac eht ni tas eilloc redrob ehT  ybigrek yb
,ti tuoba teiuq saw eH
.em ni deppop yllaer ti dna
A“ .hgiht s’tac eht gnizeeuqs ,dias ehs
,éfac eht otni yaw rieht edam ylkciuq riap ehT
.dennirg einnA ”,od uoy nehw dnA“
.nworC ehT gnihctaw tsuj saw I os taht erolpxe ot teg ot mih tnaw I ,hcum oot dnim t’ndid I
eht t’nsaw eh tespu eb d’I deirrow saw tub
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,einnA ot revo gniklaw emac neG dneirf rieht dna
.erots a morf sgniht wef a deredro dah yllautca I os ,ti tuoba tib elttil a deklat eW“
.dias ybbat llams eht
enecs eht ekorb tsomla I“
,tsrif ta esnet saw eH
.erofeb ni hcum taht muc mih tlef ev’I taht wonk t’nod I tub
.ecaf reh revo ediw daerps nirg reh
.gnihtyreve ton er’yeht tub ,nuf er’yehT
.walc a htiw gum eeffoc reh gnippat
.neG ta gnikool erofeb hcterts elttil a gnivig ,pu tas ehs dna gaw wols a evag liat reH
,einnA ekil tuls doog a eb nac enoyreve toN“ .deerga haeL
”?mottob no eb ot stnaw eh taht timda ot dessarrabme s’eh dna
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
!haeL morf pleh htiw esle gnihtemos dnif ot deganam d’ehs tub trats eht ta boj reh tsol dah neG
”.stiolpxe ym tuoba gniraeh ekil uoy wonk I tub
”,sediseB“ .dias emiaJ
.mih edor I dna nwod sgel sih tup eh ,xaler dna ecin saw eh nehW
.deksa neG ”?laer rof mih kcuf ot dnim ni enoyna evah uoY“
,etuc os saw tI !dekaeuqs eh
,yllacitsaisuhtne daeh reh deddon ehs dna ediw tnew seye s’neG
.dias einnA ”,rettam t’nseoD“
”.em rof ereht htob erew lirpA dna naD yppah tsuj m’I“
,hcum oot saw taht em dlot dna em deppots yllanif eh dna emit ruo koot eW .xaler ot detrats eh tub
”!mih fo edis tnereffid taht ot etuc saw tI
”…gnileef taht devol tsuj I dna
,enod saw eh nehW“
,mih rof delaeuqs I .tuo em
,mih ni deyats I oS
,ksed ym ta em dniheb thgir pu emac eh dna
.uoy llet ll’I ,yakO“
…ekil ot ecnahc a teg ot ecin s’tI“
,tuo semoc yllanif eh nehw oS“
.flesreh ezeeuqs a wap eerf s’neG gnivig ,elttil a depoord srae s’einnA ”.spleh
.elihw a rof taht tuoba klat ot dah I dna eh ,lleW“ .deksa neG
tib elttil a rof ti ta tpek yehT“
.hgis a devaeh yllanif ehs tub keehc reh tib dna
,efas leef t’ndid ew esuac tey ereht nettog etiuq t’nevah llits eW
!yrots ralucitrap taht morf gnimaeb saw ecaf reH
.desserped ytterp saw eh ,boj sih tsol eh retfA
,dias neG ”,lla’y sknahT“
”!ecno rof mottob no eb ot detnaw eh esuac saw eh thguoht I ahplA gib
.spil reh no krims a ,dias haeL
”,yrots taerg a saw tahT“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,delwoh dniw eht ,edistuO
.denoitidnoc neeb tsuj ev’I sseug I taht hguone snaom sih ezingocer I tub
.evissimbus dna regae os mih ees ot teews os saw tI .mih gnissik
,ni dehsup I nehw tub ,tsrif ta depmuj eH
”!uoy ees ot ecin os s’tI !einnA“
”.nuf gnivah er’uoy ekil sdnuoS
,pu gnikcit rebmun eht was nahtanoJ ,ees’Y“
.ylecin ydob reh degguh taht kceneltrut neerg a erow ehS
.ttub sih debbarg dna dniheb pu tnew I nehw
.demaeb nooccar eht ”!no oG“
doog s’ti ekil leef dna
,sdneirf owt reh erew wodniw eht edistuO
!lamron sa efil tuoba tnev dna niaga rehtegot teg yllanif ot thgir tlef tI
.toh gninrub skeehc reh
.yot eht htiw ssa sih gnikop detrats I ,tib elttil a ssa sih gnikrow retfa oS“
,niaga einnA ees ot desuhtne htob erew riap ehT .haeL dna emiaJ
.pot no bmilc dna kcab sih no mih teg I yllanif oS“
.gniog peek ot mih dlot I“
.neercs eht deppat emiaJ woh no gnidneped reteiuq ro reduol werg dna ,draeh eb dluoc zzub wol a tub
,elggig a yb nekorb saw hsulb s’einnA ”.cilbup
”?leef taht did woH“
:gnimialcorp ylduorp etiuq stigid owt ehT
.ti ot reh taeb emiaJ tub
.gniht laer eht detnaw eh tub
.did I dna ’gniog
…gnileef ecin yllaer a tsuj si hcihW
.erofeb esrow draeh s’ehs erus m’I“
…saw tI .gnola lla
.mih rof esrow ti ekam ton gniyrt
.sputeem lautriv ot kcuts d’yeht
ti gnileef t’nsaw eh
leef seugnot tac taht uoy htiw eerga nac haeL“ .dias emiaJ ”,sulP“
.elbat eht morf yawa gniretnuas ,dias ehs
.eno taht tuoba taerg leef t’nod I“
N“ .edisa ti gnihsurb rehtob t’ndid ehs dna ecaf reh otni gnillaf riah
.no bmilc ot aruaL rof hguone gnol JA ffo teg ot elba saw I“ .tol a saw tI
,elihw a rof esnet yletinifed saw tI“ .dias neG
draob eht no rebmun a teg ot gniyrt ecneirepxe dab a dah I esuaceb
,gninrom txen eht ,haey-
,syot no pu mih niart d’I ,gniklat erew ew sa wenk I dna
s’haeL ,derekcins emiaJ ”!yltsenoh
H“ .snoitseuq rieht pots ot secaf s’dneirf reh fo tnorf ni yllacitnarf meht gnivaw ,sdnah reh pu dleh einnA
.shtnom xis tuobA“ dias einnA
.ecaf reh tfel reven nirg eht tub ,elttil a deppord srae s’nooccar ehT
?wonk’y ,efas tlef I
tub mih denraw evah dluohs I
”?pup doog a mih llac uoy diD“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”?ta rebmun eht s’tahw ,em llet oS
fo sdnik lla dna ereh srehto pmud ohw elpoeP
.xes fo tniop eht t’nera smsagrO“
.retteb gnileef mih detnaw tsuj I tub
”.ti tuoba gnikniht neve yppah yllaer demees uoy tub
.seussi ytivitcennoc ro ,gal tuohtiw klat ot ,meht guh ot dehca ehS
ni flesmih devohs dna nwod meht dellup tsuj eh dna stnap agoy ni saw I
.spal rieht ni deppord yllausac os dah einnA taht noitalever eht ta deknilb slrig ehT
.pu em gnibul saw eh elihw em devol eh hcum woh dna saw I lufituaeb woh em gnillet tpek eH
,mra s’efiw reh dekcams reveirter eht hguohT ”!taerg
eht ediseb morf dias emiaJ
.su ot revo emac dna deppirts tsuj ehs os ni nioj ot detnaw ehs tub
.lacipyt ytterp ffo detrats tI“
.spil reh gnipacse elggig a ,god eht ta nikpan a dessot einnA ”!kcid s’regnarts a nwod gninrut s’ehs citnamor os s’ehs ,wwA“
Y“ .daeh reh deddon einnA
.esle gnihtyna gniyas morf emiaJ gnippots ,deganam einnA ”!yawyna-
sdrawretfa mih ot pu deldduc I .esnetni saw tI
.em devol eh hcum woh em dlot dna
.doog tlef tsuj ti dna
”?yot dettonk a nekat eh sah
.htob meht rof emac tsuj I
”?ti ekat eh did woh tuB“ “—tub dezigolopa I
.ypareht ot tnew ew yhw fo trap s’taht ,hu ,s’tahT
,daeh reh fo kcab eht no swap reh tup ehs dna pu doots srae s’einnA
”,etuc yllaer s’tahT“
,em no toof a tog s’eh
.dennirg einnA ”,uoy llet I fI“
,reh tuohtiw ti ta gniog JA dna em yb tespu t’nsaw ehS
”?yot a fo dnik tahW“ ”?krow taht seod woH“ .snoitseuq otni dedolpxe meht fo hcae erofeb deknilb oirt ehT
”!srebmun esoht fo emos tuoba raeh ot deen ew won
.elbat eht ta nemow eerht eht ot wohs ylraelc dluoc srebmun der eht os yalpsid eht delgna neG
”…tub renoos gnihtyna yas t’ndid eh das saw eh
,detrats ypareht selpuoc ,oS“
.dias amup redlo eht
tius elyts rosseforp dlo na ni ereht m’I
!yddig os tlef dna sdneirf reh ot revo dekool ehS
N“ .elttil a llef srae s’neG
.hgual tub pleh t’ndluoc emiaJ dna ,pu dekrep srae s’haeL
.oot tonk eht koot eh fi em eit mih tel d’I mih dlot I oS
.yzarc ekil gaw ot ton yrt liat sih gniees
tib a ni gnihtyna enod t’ndah eW
”…sruoy sa hcum sa ton-
.taorht reh gniraelc erofeb pil reh gnitib ffo deliart ehS ”…neeb ev’ew tuB
…ekil saw ti tub eno syawla t’nsaw I ekil toN
.deppirts dna ffo VT eht denrut I oS“
.spleh ti tub ,no dna ffO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sdrawretfa teews os saw eH .mmM …dna
.ni nael ot ylno demees neG tub
,daeh reh revo pac eht erow llits ehs dna
.ylsuoveihcsim gnikcilf seye reh ,dias einnA ”,dab toN“ .13
.eeffoc erom dah ehs gnihsiw dna puc ytpme reh ta nwod gnikool
dnif nac uoY .0102 ecnis
,elttil a depmuj eH
,yllis elttil a tlef I .delworg I tub
.gniyalpsid srebmun reh htiw ,kcen eltrut eht morf eerf ralloc nwo reh dellup ehS
.revo em tneb tsuj dna
dehsulf skeehc s’neG
”!tuls tnediser ruo tsuj s’einnA“ ”.era
.sdneirf reh ta kool ot ton gniyrt ,dias einnA
.gnilesnuoc tuoba dessarrabme leef t’noD“
.stcudorp repap yb tluassa eht ta dehgual reveirter ehT ”!hsuh uoY“
s’haeL .spat wef a ti evag dna elbat eht no enohp reh deppat emiaJ
eno siht piks esaelp
.etuc os saw eh dna
,eciton ot demees éfac eht ni eno oN
”srebmuN eht gniyalP“   yojne esaelP
”!oot ,ssem a hcus sekam eH“
.sserts emoH morf gnikroW ,snoitaniccav morf stceffe edis derapmoc yehT
,htoob eht ni efiw reh denioj eimaJ ,kcab gnilluP
,mih ta gnibbarg ,ma I ereht dna
”.deneppah gnihtyreve erofeb gniog erew I dna emiaJ
”!tops wen a dnif attog ew ,syug ,yrroS
,ybigreK yb ”srebmuN eht gniyalP“
,etatsorp sih tih I nehw dna ,emit ym koot I
,saw eh no denrut woh leef
,roolf eht no lewot eht otno gnikael saw yug rooP
,daeh reh koohs ehs dna
”.lufpleh yrev neeb sah won evah ew eno eht tub
eht ta gnikool erofeb kool a derahs emiaJ dna haeL
,pu kaeps ot htuom reh denepo einnA
”,sno-parts eht emac nehT“
”?seirots ruoy su llet reve uoy fo owt eht t’nod yhw ,emiaJ tuB
.yldduc lla gnieb erew I dna JA
,niaga gnar lleb eht nehw niaga nwod tis ot ecnahc eht dah t’ndah einnA .reh yb skooh eht no gnah ot staoc rieht einnA gnidnah
.delims einnA ”,yako s’tI“
,htoob eht ni deggaw liat s’einnA
.sdrow gnisaet s’god eht htiw pu til seye s’nooccar eht ,daeh reh gniddon ,delims neG ”.etuc saw ti dna
til srebmun eht dna ralloc reh deppat ehS
,sgnivas fo tib a dah eH
.mih ta gnikool ereht em gniees dessarrabme lla tog dna deppots eH
.ti did eh elihw mih sserdnu ot tog I dna
eugnot sih desu eh dna deksa saw I sa did I os ecaf sih no tis ot em dlot JA“
”,tseteiuq eht syawla ton er’uoY
!esae htiw tnemeticxe fo level s’reveirter eht gnihctam tac eht
,erofeb ti draeh s’ehS“
.elpuoc eht revo gnicnalg ,elttil a deggurhs neG ”…s’tI
.ffo mih ekorts tsuj
.dias emiaJ ”,teews yllaer s’tahT“
”.seog taht woh ees
.ni emac aruaL nehw s’taht dna gninaom sih htiw yob duol a gnieb saw eH
.tac reh tsniaga denael ecalp reh morf delggig haeL
.ecin os tlef tsuj I dna
noitisnart ym ni evitroppus os neeb lla ev’uoy tub
”,retal taht rof gniyap eb ll’uoy ,haeY“
llac d’I .no-parts eht ffo kcus dna eniw fo ssalg a em teg mih gnikam detrats I
.mih teg dluoc I evissimbus woh gniees ,mih gnisaet ,ssa sih gniniart tpek I tuB“
.gaw thgils a evag liat reh tub ,elttil a dehsulb eilloc ehT .dennirg haeL
.dekaos tsuj saw I dna yot eht dna htuom ym neewteb gnikcub saw eH
,ti gnidir yllaer
.cilbup ni dah snoitasrevnoc etavirp
yllausu s’einnA sa gniticxe sa ton s’ti ,haey ,hu tsuJ
,haey taht mih dlot yllanif I dna ecin os tsuj saw tI
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,mih otni dnirg ot detrats I dna deb eht otni snael dna revo seog eh tub ,regae os saw eh
,eilloc redrob eht derats tsuj oirt ehT
.edarg a nrae ot evah d’eh woh mih gnillet
.reh dniheb yaws wols a gnivig liat dna pu dekrep srae reh
lanosrep os gnihtemos yas ot drawkwa elttil a s’ti
.nwod dna pu gnivom ylwols ,elihw a rof noitisop taht tpek eH
.ffo teg ot dluoc I gnihtyna dna syot esu d’I dna ,tih tog evird xes sih nevE
”.esle enoemos deen t’nod I
dias eh dna pu ti naelc ot mih dlot dna ecaf sih ot wap ym tup I .erehwyreve
,nom’c tub ,taht htiw gnorw gnihtoN“
”,sno-parts eht gniyned ton er’uoY“
.dnopser neve dluoc einnA erofeb dias haeL
ydob ym gnibbur tpek eH
!eno taht raeh ot deen I !esaelP“
dluoc I dna ssik a em evag eH
.elihw a rof emocni ylno eht saw I tub
,ralloc a teg ot dah uoY“ .dias ehs
.reh dniheb gniggaw liat reh
,senitnarauq dna snwodkcol htiW
dairt a htiw od ot tahw wonk t’ndid ot tnew ew eno tsriF
.flesreh einnA guh dna sgod eht neewteb hsup ot eimaJ rof hguone gnol tsuj yawa gnillup ,dias haeL
.delims dna s’nooccar eht no wap a detser haeL
.em no pu kcuns tsuj ti
,sdneirf reh ot eybdoog dias ehs emit yreve tub ,tseb eht rof saw tI
.moC toD rettiwT fo ylremrof
”?denoitisop uoy erew woH“
.nooccar gnihsulb eht ta delims emiaJ dna haeL
.etib yllaer dna ffurcs sih barg dluoc I taht hguone nwod tneb eh tuB
.mraw srae reh peek ot redro ni gniraeh delffum eht gnitpecca
!emit gnol a hcus retfa
.pal sih no bmilc I
!drah eb nac taht esuac semitemos drah pu ti piz ot elba era syug desirprus m’I
traehteews a hcus saw eH
,ylhsipeehs dennirg neG
,nooccar eht ta dennirg einnA
…mu tsuj s’ti ,od yllaer I
”…taht dna traeh ot ti koot eh tub
,ris em llac ot detrats eh dna gaw ot detrats liat siH
.namow a ,wonk uoy
,ssa sih pu leef yllaer ot trats dna nwod stnap sih llup ot ecin saw tI .doog tlef tI
.ecin dna yrevihs lla em gnikam dna kcen ym gnissik saw hateehc ehT
.niaga revihs einnA gnikam dna swodniw eht gnilttar
.mih dessim I dna ynroh saw I dna truh tsuj I tub
ll’ew dna stsurt eh sdneirf emos htiw gniklat s’eh tub
.ecin os eb nac eugnot s’tac a ,hO …dna
”!nahtanoJ htiw pu dekcol raey a retfa hcum os pmuj dluow rebmun ruoy esruoc fO“ .dehgual haeL
.elzzum reh revo ediw daerps nirg a
.ot tnaw I ,on-N“ .nooccar
!gninaom no tpek flow eht tuB
.gnilesnuoc selpuoc
…I dna rehtegot eldduc ot detrats lla ew litnu meht dehctaw tsuj I dna
.elbatrofmoc saw ti erehw tsap dils dna yawa deirrac tog I lluf dna mraw os tlef I dna ecin saw tI
.ereht thgir htob meht htiw evol ni tsuj saw I dna
,erab mih gnikat ot desu m’I .pu
”,sno-parts tog eW“ .dias emiaJ
em dellif eh nehw s’taht dna muc ot detrats yllanif I os drah flesym gnibbur saw I
.haey ,etuc ytterp s’tahT“
,ti gniod reh ees t’ndid I ro
!hcum oot saw skeehc sih no hsulb etuc eht dna
”,yknik erew sdneirf ruo wenk eW“
,kool a degnahcxe emiaJ dna haeL
.ecaf reh no hsulb a fo tnih a ton htiw ,dennirg ehs
,won sraey rof yot kcuf a ekil uoy gnisu neeb s’eh
,yug roop ehT .ecaf
.tilc ym dnuora debbur eh dna demriuqs I
,einnA ta depmuj dah haeL erofeb htoob reh fo tuo ylerab saw einnA dna
.ffo mih kcus ot detrats I dnA
,nwod dekool ehs dna depoord srae s’nooccar ehT
”!eno siht wonk ot deen I
tlef I litnu gnol t’nsaw ti ,kcuF“
.tac eht otni kcab gninael ,depirg haeL
”!ti tuoba lla su llet nac uoY“
revo kcab dekool eilloc eht nehW
.oot gnilesnuoc gniod neeb evah I dna nahtanoJ“
.daeh reh fo ekahs a htiw efiw reh ta revo decnalg reveirter ehT ”!taht reh llac I nehw ti setah haeL“
”…os kniht t’nod I ,on-
em gnissik saw eH
”!ti tuoba su llet oS“
,mih truh I das saw I
,no tius a fo tib elttil a dah I
.ydaer dna ecin ssa sih teg
”!uoy ees ot doog os s’tI“
”,won nrut ruoy s’tI“
?sruoy fo eno em llet uoy lliW“
”.gnol oot yaw ni semit lamron ni neeb t’nevah ew dna semit lamron rednu ykcirt s’tI“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.tsenrae ni gnitrats morf sraet eht peek ot gniyrt ,sregnif reh htiw seye reh ta depiw neG
,ekoj a sa ti tnaem I
,gniklat detrats puorg eht oS !ylenol gnieb dna
emos gniod neeb ev’eW“
.pu denepo ppa na nehw depmuj ehs dna ediw werg seye
.yrc ot detrats tsomla I tub ,tib a truh tI
,dias einnA ”,flesmih tonk a gnikat elihw em dettonk eH“ ”.uoy
,taht yrt ot tnatiseh neeb d’eH
”.ti evig nac eh sa doog sa ti ekat nac eh dalg
,tuo gnikam ereht gnittis er’ew oS“
”,oot dnabsuh ym rof eno toG“
.tcatnoc eye ekam ot gniyrt fo sdnoces wef a retfa ssertiaw eht nwod evaw ot deganam ehS
.flow ym htiw yppah m’I dna
.daeh ym ni kcuts tog tsuj I sseug I dna
.ruf eht hguorht skeehc reh denrub llits roloc fi neve hgih pu srae reh
”?ti dah uoy evah gnol woH“
”,elbatrofmoc ton er’uoy fi su llet ot evah t’nod uoY“
.ti ta gniliaf dna nirg eht kcab etib ot gniyrt
,detartsurf saw I
.efiw reh otni denilcer ehs sa tsehc reh ot desserp daeh
.og ot retteb erehwemos ti evag I os
,pu dekrow dna ecin flesmih teg mih tel I retfA“
.emit taht lamron naht erom hcum os tlef ti tub ,ma yllausu I
”.srentrap ym htiw eb ot em rof efas dna
rennid retfa pu gninaelc pu dehsinif tsuj d’eh dna ereht erew ew ,hU ,haey-y
!sdrow s’dneirf reh fo hturt eht gniyned on saw erehT
.moC toD rettiwT fo ylremrof
htoob eht yb kcar eht no pu gnignah saw taoc reH
!taht pots ,yeh yeh-
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,ybigreK yb ”srebmuN eht gniyalP“ saw sihT
.em rof dexaler dna ,derevihs eh
.ffo deliart neG nehw rae ot rae morf gninnirg saw einnA
.nellows dna ecin gnitteg saw tonk sih ,yllanif tuB“
,ot evah t’nod uoY“
,dloheb dna ol dna
,emoh ta gniyats fo ,senohpdaeh fo derit saw ehS
.meht dniheb tsaf
em retfa eb lliw meht fo hcnub a esuaceb rehtie ti tuoba enilno dnuora gnitsop og ot tnaw t’nod eW
.seye s’dneirf reh fo hcae gnidiova
,nwod mih dleh tsuj dna tuo dellup I
.taht ekil gnihtemos tuoba ecno mih desaet evah yam I“ .pil reh tib einnA ”!dessarrabme eb ot nosaer on tog s’eh tub ,mottob ot gnitnaw mih dnim t’nod I ,onnud I“
!oot ti od dluoc eh os ,ssa ym ni tonk sih nekat ev’I tub
tnemom a rof denworf neG
ytilauxes ym htiw nepo erom leef
.elbat eht ot eson reh gnittup
!dneirf reh dnuora parw liat gnir reh gnittel neve dna god eht gnigguh
,ksa attoG“ .dias haeL
.tonk taht ekat ot krow fo tib a mih koot tI
!ssa eht pu kcoc a gniyojne mih htiw tespu eb ot gniog saw I taht deirrow yllaer saw eh kniht I dna
.mih devol I hcum woh mih dlot dna mih dessik I tub derepmihw eh ,did eh nehw tuB
,gniremmats detrats eH
,eeffoc reh morf pis a koot ehS
.reh ta gnikool saw esle eno on erus gnikam ,dnuora kool a koot dna ecaf reh fo tuo riah dekcut einnA
.tonk eht ot tsomla ti gnikat
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom
”,haeY“ .dias einnA
”?ta rebmun eht s’tahw ,oS“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
,oot ,eno duol a tahw ,saw I lrig doog a tahw em gnillet detrats ehS