.oot ti leef nac I esuaceb ,thgir uoy gnisaelp m’I wonk I
.enif saw gnihtyreve dias ssoB .tfel yeht nehT
.borhT .revihS .tsurhT
.fo elbapacnI .t’naC .t’now toN
.seitud rieht dah llits )sukraM ekil( werc lanigiro eht dna ,srekaterac sti seriuqer tiforp deniartsernu tuB
a dna meht rof laicifeneb yllautum saw taht noitulos a otni denrut melborp A
.esrow ylbaicerppa sgniht ekam ot gniog t’nsaw
taes regnessap kcab a ni gnittis dna
”?leenk ot uoy llet I nehw
.sriatsnwod deyats rehto eht elihw
,gnihtemos xif ot deen I .thguoht a dah tsuj I .oN“
.noitca eht si drihT
.boj sih ot noitnetta sih denrut dna htuom sih tuhs revird sih ,doom eht gnisneS
.ecnarebuxe gninrom sih fo lluf evalsdeb sih depmup eh sa liat sih rednu gnikcil won ,mih dewollof elzzum yretsym tahT
sukraM ,modgnik sih ssorca tuo gnikooL
.uoy llet t’nac I“
.)eninazzem eht gnitnuoc(
.pmur thgit eht otni flesmih tsurht ylizal eh sa mih dnuora tuo gnikael ”gniniart“ s’thgin tsal fo stnanmer eht leef dluoc sukraM
,sraey rof atouq woleb neeb d'yehT
.ecalp suorepsorp a saw ellivredorB
.sih htiw deniwt sregnif s’yppuP  .tuo dedeen eH
.rood eht ta mih tem yppuP
.deyebo eh taht sredro t’nerew esohT  !yebO
.sdnamed fo tsil a dna smra nepo htiw mih tem )namerof( sukraM
.hturt ni gnikcal yletanutrofnu eb ot tuo denrut dias eh gnihtemos revenehw ssa sih derevoc
.mih ta pu dekool yppuP
?uoy t’nera ,ti gnileef er’uoY“
.sllab sih ta deppal eugnot A
saw tI .ti ekil etiuq gnihtyna tlef gnivah rebmemer ecno t’ndluoc eh dna ,sraey rof ellivredorB fo reesrevo neeb dah sukraM
.retsum dessap noitanalpxe tahT .deddoN
ti gnileef yllaer—
,tluafed yb thgieh emas eht yllacinhcet erew yeht hguoht nevE
-  .gninrom rof tiaw dluoc ,saw ti revetahw ,melborp ehT
.seenk sih ot delbmuts eh ,edistuO
.yks eht otni gnisir etercnoc dna leets fo serutcurts ,nabru ylsuoegrog saw nwot elohw ehT
.wodniw eht tsniaga desserp kcab ,ylpmil gnuh eH
,eugra ot tuoba saw eH  ”.og ot deen uoY“
.ereh saw sukraM yhw saw tahT
.deb eht ot kcab deklats eh
.seye sih dih yppuP  ”?si taht dnA“
.nrecnoc suoivbo sih yawa devaw sucraM .rotavele eht ni ”srevlos melborp“ sih fo eno saw erehT
.od ton dluow sihT  .ylbbow leef
ytiruceS .daeha dellac evah tsum revirD
.deyarts noitnetta sih tub
redorB sukraM sa sukraM sa etiuq saw eno on
.erac t'ndid eh ,liat taht htaeneb pu gnidils fo yaw eht ni tog meht fo enon sa gnol sA
,llits doots sukraM
ruoy wollof lliw I .retsaM
.pleh rof ksa ot detnaw sukraM
.noitca ’srekrow txen eht rof tiaw ot evah dluow srehto dna ,fo decnivnoc eb ot flesmih wolla d’eh meht fo emoS
leef uoy od tahW“  ”.retsaM
.seye ym otni kool
,ebolg eht dnuora dettod seitic )eerht dna( derdnuh A
.gnitiaw dial nav kcalb ehT
.tnorf ’sukraM tsniaga flesmih dehsup dna
,tnemom a ni mih no saw htuom s'yppuP
.htuom ym ni pots lliw sdrow eht ,retsaM
.derreted eb flesmih tel ot gniog t’nsaw eh tub
”.od ot gniniart dennalpnu emos evah I smees tI
.enihw yppah a tuo tel dna dessap dah sdrow rof emit eht taht dediced evah ot demees eH
.reilppus a htiw elbuort neeb dah erehT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”.rehtie yas ot elba eb t’now uoy neht dna
nottub a desserp dna tuo dehcaer eH
”.taorht ym ni hctac lliw htaerB
,ereht s’ti wonk I
.tnacifingisni etiuq mees ot nwod rewoc ot deganam yppuP
.redluohs sih no ylsuousnes flesti ecalp dna
,dne yrev eht ta uoy leef nac I nehW
.ti gnileef saw eh
.od ot krow dah eh tsael ta tub ,deraeppasid t’ndah gnileef ehT
.pots deludehcsnu na saw sihT
.dluohs ti sa gnikrow saw gnihtyrevE
.rac sih otni kcab ylikahs deppets eh ,denruter sbmil sih fo lortnoc lluf htiW
.thgirpu mih tpek rood eht fo emarf eht no smra sih ylno dna ,detlem seenk siH .deen etarepsed
deifilpma sgnileef eht elihw rac sih fo rood eht no gninael
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.mih dniheb tnemeticxe sih fo selbbird elttil gnivael ,gel sih tsniaga duorp gnidnats dna drah saw yppuP taht—
.gnireviuq saw god gnileenk eht ,mih woleB
.llits egru eht leef dluoc
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
eno siht piks esaelp
.eno tsesolc eht ot tuo dehcaer eh ,tcnitsni nO
.pmur sih deppirg sregnif ybbutS
”.erusaelp ym si erusaelp ruoY
.)eltit on( redorB sukraM laer eht sa
.ti dniheb nwod neeb reven d’eh hguoht neve ,siht wenk eH
.hgih teef neves ro xis ,gnol teef neetfif ebyam ,nav kcalb A
.mih no seye rieht leef dluoc eH
,ni gnillor erew stiderC
.stfut etihw ylraep ni taocrednu dehs eerf gnillup
.ylibbarc derewsna sukraM
,eerht dna derdnuh a saw ti ,yllacinhceT
.pirg ’sukraM dnuora htaerb ni llup ot gnilggurts ,spil sih dekcil eH
.daeh sih koohs revlos-melborp ehT
yaw eht t’nsaw sihT .suovren saw eh llet dluoc sukraM
.ssecorp gninolc eht fo trap saw yromem ecnis ,syad tsrif eht rebmemer
.deredduhs sih tsniaga ydob eht dna ,enihw tfos a draeh eH
.detnetnocsid saw sukraM—
.ygolopa etamitni na ni tuo dekcilf eugnoT
.enips sih nwod elgnit wols a saw tI
,raf os gnissorC s’notnA naht retteb neeb neve dah raey sihT
.nwo sih fo efil a evil ot tuo enog dah
.srekrowkcod eht htiw gniteem a saw eludehcs sih no txeN
”.yppuP ,redro na s’tahT“  ”—I“
,dnah s’retsam sih ta deggut )evals( sukraM
uoy dluoc woH“ .delworg sukraM
.tenalp hcir-ecruoser tub ,tuo-detsalb ,nrot-raw eno dna stsilatipac dipertni derdnuh A
.sdeen MA ylrae sih ot dnetta ot
,flesti yrotcaf eht htaeneb nar taht lennut wol a ni saw eH
,tlep yerg sih ta deggut seltsirb ffitS
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,lerdnaK yb ”emaG llehS“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     .sukraM saw
did eH .emit tsal naht resolc hcum tub ,tnatsiD
nwod flesti deppird dna
,wonk dluow sukraM eht lla fo sukraM tsom ehT
.dnah a pu dleh dna )evals( sukraM ecaf ot denrut eH
.sdnoces wef a detsal ylno tI
.wodniw gnicaf-htron eht hguorht dezalb nuS
”.uoy erusaelp ot em lleT .redro yreve
.sgel s’retsam sih tsniaga ylideen ydob sih dehsup eh dna tuo deffup ruf s’yppuP
”.dnif dluoc ew taht gnihtoN .ris ,oN“
.sdrow eht si dnoceS
.mih thguac yppuP
.deddon neht ,sih otni dezag seye citamorhcoreteH
deksa eH .denruter gnileef eht nehw etupsid gnisuoh a eldnah ot nwotnwod yawflah saw eH
.revo nwot txen eht ot tcudorp ekat ot srevird lufitud rieht rof
.detixe dah sukraM retfa ybbol eht ot nwod kcab ti edor dna
.wobniar citoahc eht ni ereht nwod morf eman sih gnillac saw gnihtemoS  .t’nsaw eH
.kcab dellup neht
.emoh denruter eh nehw emithcnul retfa saw tI
.syob ,syot ruoy yawa tuP“
redluohs sih tsniaga gnikcilf srae fo riap a leef dluoc eh taht tcaf ehT
”.ekil s’ti tahw em lleT
.deraelc neeb dah ciffart ,meht fo daehA
.ylla erutuf elbissop
.gninrom yreve mih ta rorrim eht fo tuo dekool taht seno eht fo esrever eht erew yeht—seye esoht otni gnirats ddo saw tI
.enil eht nwod yaw eht lla noitcudorp yaled ,dlot saw eh ,dluow sihT
.deirrow dekool sgel sih neewteb nwod ecaf ehT
.dnoces a rof ylno despmilg
.enihw rehtona draeh sukraM ,mih dniheB
.pord mih tel sukraM
.taht dias d’eh yhw derednow eh ,daeh sih edisnI
.em pleh esaelP .evael t’nod esaelP
.deraeppasid erutsop suoixna eht dna ,srae s’yppuP ekorts ot nwod dehcaer eH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.drow rehtona tuohtiw rood eht sdrawot denrut eh sa deppord sih gnidloh dnah eht ,daetsnI
.thginot secnabrutsid oN“
.denihw dna nihc sih htaeneb tuons a dehsup enoemoS
.msagro sih fo stnanmer eht pu kcil ot ylregae ni deppid elzzum eht ,tuo dellup eh nehW
,divoloh eht no gnineve yreve swen eht evag )namsekops( redorB sukraM
.gnicsinimer sih detpurretni gniteem txen sih ot rood eht gninepo revirD
.teg dluoc yeht taht esoht fo lla fo deen ni erew yehT
.erehwesle dedeen saw eh dna
,sukraM saw ellivredorB ni enoyreve ,tcaf nI
.eciov eht si tsriF“  ”.yakO“
,oN .yawa edaf ot smees em dnuora esle gnihtyrevE
.guh ot ydob a dnuof
ta yb dehsalf sthgiL
.mih rof deggaw yeht dna ,srae rieht no sdnah dial eH
.gnorW saw gnihtemoS
.olah a ekil mih til tlep enitsirp sih fo egnirf eht ,mih dnuorA
.tuo dnah sih dleh eh nehw mlap ’sukraM otni dehsup eson regae nA
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.ni dehsur neeb dah sloot tnemecalper elihw keew a rof noitcudorp dellats
.ti rof deksa d’eh ,llits tub—syad wef txen eht rof eros ytterp eb ylbaborp d’eH
.mih rednu deliaf dna
”.uoy ot ti nialpxe nac I erus ton m’I .t’nac I“
”.em rof gnihtemos od ot uoy tnaw I ,yppuP“
,redro rehtona tuo krab ot tuoba saw eH .raeh ot detnaw sukraM redro eht t’nsaw sihT  ”.seye
sukraM lanigiro eht—sukraM
.mih noitseuq ot ecalp rieht t’nsaw tI .meht derongi eH
dna dellor eh ,desolc llits seyE
.ecived eht morf pu
s’)evals( sukraM hguorht yaw sti krow ot noitseuq eht rof emit emos koot tI  ”?yppuP
.oiduts sih otni mih dewollof god elbaticxe eht dna ,srae s’yppuP dehctarcs eH
.daed tnew enil ehT
.traeh eht evah t’ndid eH
.ruoh rep selim derdnuh a
.siht ekil tsuj stnemom rof dnuora tnempiuqe dlo eht evah ot tnatropmi saw ti tlef llits eh tub ,emoh sih ni sruoh gnol rof dellac ylerar syad esehT
.noitcesretni yreve ta meht tem sthgil neerG
.mih ot txen ydob a saw erehT
.otni gnidils saw eh dne liat esohw fo noitseuq eht derewsna taht ,lleW
,wodniw htgnel-ydob eht fo noitcelfer krad eht nI
.tca ot desoppus saw ris
,htap sih morf yawa dezinagro neeb dah seirevileD .eludehcs sih rof tuo dennalp neeb dah gnihtyrevE
.thgieh lluf sih ot dnats yppuP ees ot egnarts saw tI
.eta eh sa hsurb a htiw mih dednetta yppuP
.etad retal emos ta ti rof yppuP drawer ot eton latnem a edam eH
.slennut eht fo shtped eht otni nwod detarelecca nav eht dna ,stnemom tsuj ni detapissid sgnileef ehT
,)snoitulos( sukraM ni thguorb mocretni eht no llac A
.selkna sih no sdnah erew erehT
.tnemeticxe gninrom sih dnuora depparw eugnot s’enoemos htiw remraw neve dna ,thgilnus eht ni mraW
.kcohs dna noisufnoc denibmoc ni deworran erew seyE
.detpecca ygolopA .dooG
,snoitulba gninrom ,rewohS
.nwod meht devaw eH .trela no llits saw ytiruces ,ybbol eht nI
,niaga on yas ot evah t’now I nehT .dooG“
.pu kcab kcip ot tey llits dah noitcudorp dna
,oga shtnom wef a ereht nwod serif neeb d’erehT
.redluohs sih ot nepo gnurps tI
.tpa saw ,secnatsmucric eht ni ,hcihW
.dnim sih ni dehsalps gnilgnit ehT
,retsaM ,oot noos wonk ll’uoy neht—
,liated erom em evig ot evah ot gniog er’uoY“
.erehwemos kcots fo htrow s’keew a dnif t’ndid yeht fi noitcudorp fo smret ni gnissorC s’notnA fo daeha ellivredorB peek ot gniog erew seigolopa fo tnuoma on tub ,sesimorp dna seigolopa htiw mirb eht ot lluf saw pillihP sihT .thgirb sa flah tuoba dna sukraM dradnats ruoy sa llat sa eciwt ,sesroh elbailer dna dilos erew yehT .spillihP wef a tem dah sukraM .)ytilibatnuocca dna stnuocca( pillihP saw gniteem eht no ni gnittiS
.ksam laicaf sih dehtooms bmoc niht a sa llits daeh sih dleh dna
,wonk I esuaceb dna ,wonk I
.thguoht ni doots eh sa elzzum eht bur dna nwod hcaer mih edam egru suoicsnocbus A  ”.retsaM ,yppaH“
yojne esaelP   .yrruFoS no
.nac uoy wonk I tub ,netfo klat ton yam uoY .taht od t’noD“
.ereht t’nsaw taht eciov a rof netsil ot gninrut srae sih tlef eH !emoC
,lerdnaK yb ”emaG llehS“
renwo sti dnuof tub
tnetepmoc sa erew ellivredorB ni sdnah s’eno on dna
dna seruliaf sih fo hguone dah d’eh dediced dah rorrim eht ni erugif eht fi sa saw tI
.od ot em gnillet er’uoy tahw rettam t’nseod tI
.sredorB sukraM ynam erew erehT  2 fo 1 traP
,ekil ti si tahW“
,sexof lacitnedi sseltnuoc fo dlrow a enigami ot deirt ohw
,oga sraey ythgie dednal werc noteleks a htiw pihs elgnis A
a saw ,hguoht ,yranidro eht fo tuO
.uoy rof erom evah I“
.level dnuorg morf teef fo sderdnuh saw ti hguoht neve
.derednaw sdnah ehT
.esnopser ylno sih saw enihw desufnoc dna tfos A .daeh
,kcots munimula rieht fo ecruos eht ,notpillihP
.notselrahC ni nwod erew yeht naht ereh retteb erew sgniht yletinifeD
,tuo trihs sih deffup htaerb toH
.s’yppuP ekil tsuJ
.wonk t’now yppuP taht dna—
.rehto hcae ta derats yeht
.revocer ot stnemom wef a sukraM koot tI  ”.pleh t’now tI“
.ot em llet yllacificeps t’ndid uoy nehw neve
sdnammoc ehT !leenK !tiS !emoC
moor sih fo moolg eht morf flesti hcated elzzum a ees dluoc eh
reilrae ti ot thguorb neeb dah noitnetta esuaceb ylno—deton sukraM
”?esle gnihtynA .ssob seY“
.mih rof gnitiaw saw tsafkaerb suoutpmus a neht
.denruter noisufnoC .deppots
.)reganam secruoser( sukraM dna )yraterces lloryap( sukraM fo noinu eht sselb ot nwotnwod dedeen saw eh ,taht retfA
,dedeen yeht tahw laets neve ro ,worrob ,geb ot erew sesukraM fo maet ehT
,ytissecen fo nrob saw citehtsea ehT
.shgiht sih tsniaga derekcilf sraE
.raeh yllaiciffo ot ton esohc eh srepsihw draeh eH
.munimula eht ni tned htooms a dniheb tfel eH
,pu ti thguorb yppuP taht woN
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ekahs sdnah sih edam tI
.niaga llams raeppa ot deripsnoc eH
.ylbisiv dexaler stsev foorp-tellub ni sesukraM ruoF ”.won
”.tnemtrapa eht ni kcab
,srettam ti fo enon tub
.derdnuh owt eb dluoc tI  .owt eb dluoc tI
.yrots eht rof retteb hcum os tlef srebmun dnuor tub
?ees uoy od ,yawyna emas eht lla s’taht dne eht ni tub ,ti od ot em tnaw uoy esuaceb ti od ot tnaw ylno I semitemoS
.ssenisub htiw ysub saw eh nehw tpurretni ot ton wenk evalS
.dnik er’uoy ,retsaM“
.dnah ruoy deen t’nod I tub
seye sih desolc eH
,steerts dedduts-yksuh eht otno nwod thgil gnilkniwt rieht enihs ot niav ni deirt srats fo noitcelloc yeltom a ,evobA
.ti dniF .oot ti was revirD“  ”.sruo fo eno toN“
”?slleb yna gniR .noitcerid yreve ni swodniw kraD
,dewols revird siH ”.potS“
.regnorts gniworg saw gnileef ehT  ”.t’nac
”.deb ot kcab emoC“
,lerdnaK yb ”emaG llehS“
enihw ehT  ”.uoy esaelp ot em redro ot uoy tnaw I ,yppuP“
.llirht eht leef dluoc sukraM
.ylleb sih tsniaga dehsup lruc-liat A
.niaga wodniw eht fo tnorf ni deppots eH
,daed eb ll’I nehT“
?nwo ruoy enolc tsuj nac uoy nehw srekrow tropmi yhW
.ti ni t'nsaw tsuj dnim siH
.)snoitaler( sukraM htiw tem eh sriatsnwoD
.sukraM laer eht si ohw tuo dnif ot
.spil sih dekcil revirD  ”.oN“
.mlap sih otni pu dehsup eson a sregnif sih htaenrednu dna ,daeh s’draug eht debbur eH
.nus eht dedulcco ydob siH
”?thgin tsal morf gnihtynA“
.esuohtnep eht ot kcab delf yeht sa tsap gnihsalf detrats sthgil dna
.eslup ot nageb thgil neerg htooms a ,regnif sih fo erusserp eht ta dna ,ynihs saw tI
.rekrow doog yrev a t'nsaw
,yrotcaf eht ta reenigne dael eht saw )namerof( redorB sukraM
.tlep kciht sih hguorht edils sdnah tlef—
.elbitsiserri erew
.laeppa nairatilitu sti detaicerppa sukraM tub
dluoc enoyrevE  .sraey ythgie tsal eht ni hcum os degnahc d'tI
.edam si tiforp woh s'tahT
dna spillihP deniart ylhgih owt dellik dah taht tluaf yrotcaf a dah
.dnammoc a em gnivig er’uoy esuaceb
seidob owt ,tcaf ni ,erew ereht taht mih demrofni
ygro suotoir a dednetta dah
!mih saw ti ,ereh sredro tuo krab ot gniog saw enoyna fi dna ,sukraM
.ytnewt derdnuh a ta lennut eht morf ekorb yehT
dnah ruoy esu em tel dna dnuora hcaer syawla uoY
.ylf sih yb dewollof ,ffo tleb sih deirp sregnif dna
.t’ndid seye rehto eht ,edis eht ot dekcilf ezag sih nehw tuB
,nwotnwod gniltsub eht dekoolrevo tnemtrapa esuohtnep siH
.yad eht ecaf ot ydaer tlef dna dehsinif eh nehw nevele saw tI
,dworc eht ot tsol gnol ,dneirf dlo na fo thgis eht saw tI .ezingocer dluohs eh wenk eh eciov esohw enoemos fo ohce tnatsid eht saw tI
rood seireviled tauqs a saw smoor ecnerefnoc eht dniheb dna rotavele eht fo kcab eht dnuorA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.rotces eht flah ot tcudorp tuo gnippihs
.seenk sih ot kcab knas eh dna ,tsrif llef ezag s’yppuP
.nemssenisub gnirad lanigiro esoht fo eno fo tnemtsevni eht eno hcae
.swodniw sih tsap dehsalf sgnidliub s'ellivredorB fo sbals ykcolb eht sa rednaw dnim sih tel dna mih fo daeha evird etunim ytnewt a dah eH
”?retsaM ,uoy desaelpsid t’nevah I epoh I“
”.tuoba wonk ot deen uoy gnihtoN“
.kcen sih yb pu yppuP deluah dna nwod denael sukraM
.sreksihw sih deneerp bmoc renif neve nA
.edisni mih dewollof yehT
.od ot tnaw I gnihtemos od ot
.evocla na otni tes ksed mils a ot denrut eh
.ffo thgin eht ekaT“
.til sthgildaeh s’nav kcalb eht erofeb tog eh lla saw drawrof pets ykahs enO
.gninihw saw yppuP esirprus oN
.gniht citnehtua eht meht fo eno yreve dna hcae
.flesmih dnefed ot yrt t’ndid yppuP ”.yas t’nac I
.tahw ot degnoleb ohw fo kcart peek ot gniyrt deppots eh tniop siht ta saw tI
.hcamots sih revo ruf tfos eht hguorht deffup htaerb toh dna
,dnah decitcarp a deriuqer stiforp esohT
,dnuora gninrut rac eht leef dluoc sukraM ,flesti dehsinif noitseuq eht erofeb nevE
.rovas ot dednetni eh erusaelp a saw gnikaW
”.uoy llet nac I gniht eno s’ereht tuB“
roolf driht-ytnewt eht no tnecserC teertS hgiH 8 ni devil eH .)eltit on(
.ciporhtnalihp rehtar gnileef saw sukraM ,gniteem eht fo dne eht yB
.ni devil eb ot deen etanutrofnu rieht fo ailanrehparap rehto dna
.rof deksa yeht gnihtyreve teg t’ndid yeht fi neve ,deniag neeb dah dnuorg ekil gnileef emoh og dluow enoyrevE
,taht od em gnittel eunitnoc ot uoy tnaw I esuaceb ,yaw gnorw eht siht ekat t’nod esaelP
.yrautca sih saw )tnatnuocca( redorB sukraM elihw
.dekool eh naht reivaeh saw evalsdeb sih—thgiew eht tfil ot niarts ot dah eH
.wollof t’nac I tahT“  ”!redro na s’tahT“  ”.on gniyas
ot gnignol lareneg morf
.serutcurts detacirbaf-erp lufesu fo rebmun yna otni denrut eb ot ydaer
.wonk t'ndid eH  ?mih htiw deb ni erew seiksuh ykaens ynam woH
,rotavele eht otni mih dewollof eno tahT .egrahc ni eb ot demees meht fo enO
.dehsinif yppuP sa elzzum sih ta deppal yltfos eugnot A
.yldas daeh sih koohs )evals( sukraM
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,retsaM .hsiw uoy fI“
.gniggaw erew sliat rieht taht deton eH
.rorrim weiv raer eht ni mih gnihctaw seye
.tnelis saw edir eht fo tser ehT
syawla s’ti ,em redro uoy nehW
,erutcurtsarfni gnivirht a saw tenalp eht won dna
)yenrotta( redorB sukraM elihw
.pihsrow yppuP dna ni gnipeels dna slaem suoutpmus lla t'nsaw efiL
.mih ot kcab emoc ot demees ecalp sih fo esnes emoS
,retsaM ,ot em tnaw uoy esuaceB“  ”?yhW“
.sgel sih ot flesti desserp ydob a dna delffuhs sgeL
.ti tsniaga thgiew sih werht dna rood eht ot teef net tsal eht nar eH
.sehtolc ”s’revloS melborP“ sa wonk ot emoc dah sukraM tahw ni seiksuh owt htiw gnola ,meht rof gnitiaw saw
eye eht ot gnisaelp saw ti dnuora esle gnihtyrevE .sgnidliub tes-wol rehto eht lla evoba derewot tI
.rac suoiruxul a edisni bruc eht ta tuo mih rof gnitiaw saw )revird( sukraM
I tub ,sruoy si ydob ym dna ,esle gnihtynA
.thgin ta did ti naht tnereffid tib a etiuq dekool ellivredorB ,thgilnus thgirb eht nI
.rovaf a teg dluow notselrahC dna
”.wenk uoy woh wonk ot tnaw I .em erusaelp
dekil eh ,retsulb sih lla roF
.tnemhcated rieht ni suoiciled ,snoitasnes detcennocsid lla erew yehT
roloc fo sehctap gniltrats htiw ,etihw dna tfoS
.uoy stceffa gniod m’I tahw woh tsuj leef nac I dna ,tnaw uoy tahw llet nac I
ssem a edam I taht yrgna eb thgim uoy esuaceb ,yrdnual eht od em tel uoy doog s’tI …llew
.spil fo gnikcams a draeh dna hctorc sih morf yawa kcab daeh s'yppuP dehsup eH
.xob kcalb hsilyts a no
,trihs ’sucraM rednu pu debbur sdnaH
.ysaeuq tlef eh dna ,ylbbow erew seenk siH
.kcab sih dniheb meht depsalc eH
,tuo gnidloffacs emarf raludom dna ni slairetam waR
,srood ,swodniw rof pu nekorb erew sepahs eht erehw
.evissam dna gnikluh ,nwot fo retnec eht ni hctolb nworb dna yerg a saw yrotcaf ehT
emit thgin eht rof gnitiaw selcihev yreviled elibommi htiw deggolc
.delbbow seenk sih ,erofeb ekil tsuJ
,nepo saw rood edis ehT
”?pleh lacidem rof llac I dluohS“
.mih rof yaw edam sesukraM ressel eht ,tnew sukraM reverehW
.ecnereffid eht edam taht hcuot lanosrep eht saw tI
.retaw eci ni daeh sih deknud d’eh fi sa saw tI
,deksa sukraM ,emit emos retfA
erew yeht dna—gnicitne erew seliw s’gnihtyalp sih hguoht neve roF  .elibommi
,esaelP“  ”—wonk ylbissop
.dniheb yab gnidaol a dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,deppots sdnah ehT  ”?yrT“
detulas mih htiw rotavele eht gnirahs yksuh ehT
.notselrahC ot )snoitaler( sukraM wollof ot saw ohw
”?on yas ot egru eht teg reve uoy t’nod tuB“
.redluohs sih no gnitser daeh eht desserac dna dnah sih desiar eH
ekil t’nod I .retsaM
,tuons s’)evals( sukraM dnuora pirg nori na htiW
.tnemom a rof kniht ot demees revirD
!gninnur sraey evif raey eht fo recudorp eht now d’yeht dna
,ellivredorB fo lla ni tuB
yaled s’keew a dna
.noitativni na sa taht koot yppuP
.noitnetta latot ym sdnamed eciov ruoy s’ti taht tcaf eht tsuJ
.sgel sih neewteb pu delruc saw liat siH
.tuo deppets dna rac eht pots ot revird
seenk sih gnikam saw gnileef eht tsuj ,llitS
”?yrt uoy litnu wonk uoy od woH“
.emit emas eht ta evitcartta dna tnelleper htob
,eye ot eyE .elzzum sih koot dna tuo dehcaer yppuP tub
ot uoy tnaw t’nod I“
selrahC eussi-dradnats eht ,sraey ythgie retfa taht tuo denrut tI .ereht nwod dab ydaerla erew sgnihT
.kcab sih tsniaga sevlesmeht tif ymotana fo seceip tfos dna gnitseretni suoiraV
.ytnewt ebyaM .neT
”?meht ot og ot stnaw ydob ruoy dna ,eman ruoy gnillac s’enoemos ekil s’tI
.dekwauqs xob eht ,mih dniheB
!leeH !emoC ot mih dlot taht eson sih ssorca ksum fo tnecs eltbus a saw tI
wobniar a fi sa saw tI
.ylleb ’sukraM ot talf flesti dehsup elzzum s’yppuP
.yppah neeb evah dluohs sukraM
,gnisselb a dias )redael lautirips( sukraM
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.won thgiR .og ot deen
deprihc eciov a erofeb sdnoces eerht naht erom tiaw ot evah t’ndid eH
diuqil tnew sgel siH
.delkcuhc mocretni eht no eciov ehT
”.wodniw siht hguorht uoy tup ll’I dna ’on‘ erom enO ?yhW“
,syaw emos nI .suoecavruc dna htooms dna etihw—
.doots )evals( sukraM ,ylwolS
”?ris ,taht saw tahW“
.seiksuh fo mih dednimer sgnidliub eht
secaf etihw-maerc fo aes gnillim eht detniap sngis noen gniralb sa ,sroloc fo pirt dica na saw weiv eht ,won thgiR
,senihw evitnialp s’)evals( sukraM gnirongI
.hguorht nevird saw eh sa neerg yltneinevnoc erew sthgil teerts dna
.hgiht sih dnuora desolc sregniF
.won detros lla s’tI .draug lamron eht evael tsuJ
.dekrow dna devil seiksuh lacitnedi sseltnuoc erehw
.tenalpruF no elbaliava si
”.od nac I gnihtemos s’ti dna
.egamulp ylthgin s’ellivredorB fo yalpsid yduag eht ni denword yletamitlu erew tub
”.enif s’gnihtyrevE
,aipotsyd otni evled tnecer tsom rieht ,dlrowpU nwoD gnignirB
.deraelc taorht A
ti od ylno nac I tub
shgiht sih gnilkcit rehtona dna
.der nar noisiv siH
”.krow t’now ti tub ,od ot uoy llet ot em tnaw uoy revetahw od ot uoy llet dluoc I“  ”?tahW“
.sukraM lacipyt—eulb saw rehto eht dna ,neerg-wolley saw enO
.ygolopa na rof stnemegnarra edam dah yppuP deraeppa tI
…niks ym otno nwod gnilbbird dna ruf ym ni gnidnal s’ti ro ,em edisni gnitrups er’uoy dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.erom gnihtyna deen t’nod I
,llew devil ytic eht ni enoyreve ton hguoht neve dna
”?ris ,yako gnileef uoy erA“  ”.emoh em ekaT“
.sksam detnit-nomannic dna
.sesukraM gnitiaw eht otno
.llac eht draeh eh ,niaga tub
ti gnileef er’uoy fI“
.won esolc saw llac ehT
.yppuP sih saw teef sih ta eldnub gniyrc elttil eht tub ,nwot eht ni sesukraM lla fo tsael eht eb thgim eH .yppuP
”.ylenol si yppup ruoY ?esaelP“
.ssuf fo muminim a htiw nwot-ssorc mih deirref )revird( sukraM
.enif ton saw gnihtyrevE
,esuohtnep sih fo roolf eht hguorht pu gnipees ti leef dluoc sukraM
,trihs denottub-flah sih rednu pu demrow eson ehT
”.noitamrofni emos em teG .ti niateD
.gnimaercs hcum oot saw ereht tub
.yppup doog a m’I
.skcurt gnikluh eht neewteb ni dereknuh tI .nav kcalb
”!niaga uoy ksa t’now I ,yppuP“
.setar drocer ta tcudorp gnicudorp dna yawa gnigguhc saw—sevlesmih yb yleritne dennam—nwot fo retnec eht ta yrotcaf ehT
,dnah ruoy esu em tel ot tegrof uoy taht krow htiw ysub os er’uoy nehw ,semitemoS
eht saw eh—sukraM yna tsuj t’nsaw eH
.mih ta pu dekool elzzum suoiruc a ,hctorc sih morF
rewol tlenk yppuP ,taorht sih ni gnidliub saw taht lworg eht tA
.mih sa llat sa tsuj saw yppuP taht togrof sukraM semitemos taht gnileenk dna tneb dna delruc emit hcum os tneps eH
emit txen ni enuT
.ecnartne niam eht ekat t’ndid eH  ?eh t’ndluow
.retsam doog a er’uoy esuaceb
”.thgir ton s’gnihtemoS .syab gnidaol dna nur niam eht ot nwod syob eht ekaT“  ”?ssoB“
.emit siht etaidemmi saw rewsna ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA  !?UOY LLIW RO
yppuP rehtona ekam meht evah ot deen ll’uoy dna