.dlrow eht sllif wodahs siH
gniniamer ,sthguoht eht ,thgil eht lla dnA
.ssenkrad ni era ew ,thgil fo tsdim eht nI .mih hguorht deretlif erA
.enilwaj ym no swodahs eht nopu ,keehc ym nopu tser lliW noitcafsitas ni dnah sih llit setunim fo rettam erem A
,enilwaj sih no swodahs eht fo
.yletelpmoc sih eb em tel ,neht ,gninrom-dim ni tesnus fO tnemom a tsuj roF ?stsal ti elihw ,tnemom siht etsat ton yhw oS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
yrteop sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf seirots ni deddebme
.aneyH desopmoC a ,ssorC yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,floWcaM boR yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT
roloc eht denrut sah thgil ehT
.gnittes si nus eht ,noom eht nO
eno siht piks esaelp
yadrutaS ,espilcE raloS“   yojne esaelP
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,espilcE raloS“ saw sihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ot tpmetta t'now tub od ot yrt dluoc lliw ym gnihtyna fO
.egap yrrufoS sih no dna yteicoS
.gnihton od nac I ?I dnA .enilwaj sih no
.noisiv ym tuo nrub lliw I
”htneT rebotcO yadrutaS
pihsrow dna ,etsat dna ,wob dna ,leenk si od nac I taht tsael ehT ?ecafrus
.tesnus s'ti tbuod ton od dnA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
floWcaM boR yb meop a ,”htneT rebotcO
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
ranul morf em hcaer ot rehtob tesnus dluow yhw dnA
:mih ta kool ton dluohs I yas yehT
.aneyH desopmoC a ,ssorC yb daeR
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
sseldrager gnineppah si sihT
?pihsrow dna daeh ym wob ton yhw oS ?leenk ton I dluohs yhw oS
?gnikool ton yb noisiv sih peek ot nam a ti stiforp tahW
htaeneb seye gniveirg ym tser ton yhW
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
?wodahs dlog llud sih
,yllaretil gnikat htrow ton rohpatem a derevocsid reven sah ohw
.ecafrus ranul morf em ot ,neht ,tesnus fo hcaer eht gnol woH
elbbuts dna ruf fo tnecs eht fo roloc ehT