".enola ti evaeL .xof ,dneirf tseb ym uoy ekam t'nseod tonskcoc gnilgraG“
.evah t'ndluohs eh gnihtyna was eh erofeb seye sih detreva surriS tub
.niaga delkcuhc tsuj flow ehT
”maetS“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT      .rac sih ot
.ereht ruf enif eht ta gnikorts dap bmuht tfos a
.ffo surriS teg ot desu d'eh naht
.lla tA .tuo t'nsaw eH
sgut wef a htiw depleh evah thgim eloC hguohtla
,od ot tnaw uoy od tahW .yllanoisaccO .ffo syad evah od I ,haey …tuB
surriS tuohtiw klat ot meht rof hguone esolc saw tI
taht tub ,mih naht rellat sehcni wef a saw eloC ,eruS .sih
gnikcilf pu dedne eh dna regnif elddim sih ot kcuts saw mucerp fo dnarts elgnis A
.tuo klaw dna pu teg tsuj ot detnaw surriS fo trap A
.elims a decrof surriS
,erehwemos gnidih saw srekrowoc rehto sih fo eno fi ees ot gniyrt ,moor eht dnuora dekool surriS sa nevE
".eivom a dna rennid gniod ton m'I tub ,gnihtemos ro srewolf uoy yub nac I
.desuora teg ot erew eh fi
".ekil uoy lla kooL
".syad eseht no gniog
.xof eht fo tnorf ni gnileenk
naelc flesmih deugnot tsuj xof eht tub
"?seitinutroppO“  ".uoy htiw evol ni yldam llaf dna teef ruoy ffo
,tnemom a rof deppord seye 'surriS
tnereffid ehT .seiceps tnereffid rof dezis erew hcihw fo emos ,sehcneb fo sreit eerht erew erehT
".tnaw I revenehw yaw taht ffo skcor ym teg nac I ekil ton s'ti os nwot ni syug fo tol a t'nera ereht uoy dlot tsuj I dnA
.ezeeuqs elpmis a htiw etacinummoc ot deirt eh ",enif si sihT“
.taht naht retteb od ot dednetni eloC hguoht
,senipluv sa erutcurts dna epahs emas eht ylhguor dah sdinac wenk eH
,wap sih htiw snoisses gnol sih dna seisatnaf ynam sih lla nI
.snoitom ydaets ,wols ni nwod dna pu elzzum sih gnivom ylsuoenatlumis
.ti tuoba looc eb d'yeht tbuod I
",pu tuhs ot nehw wonk t'nseod ohw rekcufrehtom rettib a m'I esuaceB“
,sdnoces wef a rof tcatnoc eye ekam ot deganam surriS
"?naem uoy od tahW“ .niaga nepo seye
.delkcuhc eloC  "!erats t'nod I
.snaej sih fo tekcop tnorf eht ni meht decalp dna gab sih morf syek sih dellup eh sa
,retal setunim wef A  2 fo 2 traP
gnikael llits saw eloC
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,ryC rohtarB yb
.daeh sih dniheb ti dekcut dna
.ereht rof gnikool saw eh tahw fo erusnu
,gnitnap ydaerla saw eh taht neviG .taeh fo seerged tnereffid
relluf gnikool saw
,spil sih dekcil surriS
taht won dna truh ot gnitrats erew seenk siH
dessap ydaerla d'eh
.swap sih gnisu yb ecneirepxe elbarusaelp a ti gnikam fo
".evil ot yaw ylenol a ekil sdnuos tahT“
".pu tnep teg I semitemos ,yawynA“
.stnemevom etarebiled
".trevrep a era yllaer uoY“
,shgiht sih pu raf ytterp gnidir saw lewot sih fo mottob eht ,ti revo dessorc elkna na dna desiar eenk eno htiW
,gnibborht deppots kcid s'flow eht ecno tonk sih desaeler surriS
.sseltniop tib a ytsedom fo tca eht edam ylenecsbo tuo deglub ti yaw eht hguohtla
.tis ot erehw gnidiced fo esneterp eht rednu
.revetahw ro kcab em teg ot deen oN .dehcatta sgnirts oN
.deooc eh ",dooG .dooG“
,dessap setunim wef A
.uoy retfa gniloord em ekil syug evah ot gniog er'uoy ,tesolc eht fo tuo er'uoy ecnO
.taht ta dehgual eloC ,nosaer emos roF
.enot desuma na ni dias flow eht
.tnatropminu sa gniht elohw eht ssimsid ot fi sa wap a devaw neht
,muc s'eloC fo etsat gniregnil eht htiw ylegnarts denibmoc rovalf ehT
,dehguoc eh sa dna
wap eht htiW .mih dleh taht eciv tevlev eht ot erusserp gnidda dna
".yrt ot tnaw uoy fi on yas annog ton m'I tub
redduhs ot nageb neht
"?xesttub dna sbojwolb htiw gnorw s'tahW“
.daer dluoc xof eht taht ereht gnihton saw erehT
suoivbo os eb t'now uoy ,metsys ruoy fo tuo ti teg uoy fi ebyaM
.seye sih ni kool gninoitseuq a dah xof ehT  ".deneppah reven
.kcirp sih fo pit eht htiw elzzum 'surriS fo edis eht dekcams dna
.emit siht ylitraeh erom elttil a dehgual flow ehT
.psag teiuq a gniticile
",srae dna eson a evah llits I tub ,desolc seye ym evah yam I“  .esle gnihtyna
,lewot eht yb delaecnoc llits
noitseuq nekopsnu s'flow eht rewsna ot flesmih gnirb t'ndluoc eH
.rae sih fo egde eht tem placs sih erehw tops evitisnes eht ta hctarcs ot nageb regnif xedni gnol sih dna
ytilauq ycips tsomla
.pu delir uoy nettog s'gnihtemos taht llems nac I dna
.teef sih ot tog neht
.ydob ecin a daH .doog dellems eH
,htaehs sih fo egde kcalb eht tsniaga
.dnim ruoy egnahc uoy fi wonk em tel ,yawynA“
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
seenk sih no neeb d'eh elihw esolc nettog d'eH
,erofeb kcid dekcus reven ev'uoy fi tub ,ffo teg ot gnol em ekat t'now tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
yrruFoS gnidulcni
em detpurretni uoy ,wonk uoY“
a dezeeuqs eh hguoht dna
.seirrebwarts ekil yllaer I ,haeY .hO“
.retteb hcum t'nera srewohs ehT .ssorg si
,noisicerp fo level taht htiw smirt ydob lluf od dluow ohw snolas ytlaiceps fo wenk eH
,ylprahs delahxe flow eht
rac sih ni tuo eno gnizeeuqs ot troser ot evah t'ndluow eh ebyam taht dezilaer ylkciuq eloC dna
.kcohs a llits saw ti tub ,gnitseggus saw eh tahw wenk surriS
.slewot loop derednual ylhserf eht fo eno saw mih htiw thguorb eh llA
aera cibup s'xof eht tsniaga
.gnirats tsuj er'uoy dna teffub kcid
.sgel s'elam rehto eht neewteb kcoc kciht eht ot dellup gnieb llits saw noitnetta sih tub
.htaehs sih ni llits redniamer nellows eht nwod neht
.drazzilB eht otni tuo deppets yeht dna dekrims eloC  ".ssA“
,evitcepsrep s'xof eht morf tsael ta ,noitapicitna fo sdnoces gnizinoga lareves retfA  .hguone gnol
.tnedicni regit eht retfa gab sih ni kcap a gnipeek fo tibah a edam d'eH
t'nsaw ti ,ohw em llet t'ndluow dna ti tuoba yoc tog ehs nehw tub ,teem dluohs I taht dneirf yag a dah ehs taht detnih ahsirT ,naem I .em dlot eno oN“
mih deflugne ylkciuq wam regral s'flow eht nehw depsag eh tub
,ti otni yltcerid elzzun ot ton troffe koot ti taht gnimlac dna larutan os tlef ecaf sih gnippuc wap ehT ?ebyam ,ytirecniS
",siht deen od yllaer uoy sseug I .xof ,KO“
.epahs doog ni saw yllaer eH
wap mrif a decalp flow eht ,oS
.raey fo emit siht teg ot drah er'yehT
,niaga desolc erew seye s'eloC ,trap sih roF  .drager taht ni
.flow eht morf ssorca yltcerid hcneb a otno delttes yllanif eh os
.elims a pleh t'ndluoc surriS
nwod gnizeeuqs dna tonk s'enipluv eht dnuora tsif a gnipparw yb
gnipleh eb ot mees did anuas eht dna
.xaler nac uoy fi retteb leef ll'tI“
I tub ,ecalp thgir eht ni s'traeh ruoy wonk I ,netsiL“
,drawkwa yllanoitpecxe neeb dah tI .deggurhs
dna seye sih desolc tsuj flow eht sa deganam surriS
kcab nward seye sih dnuof eh ,revewoh ,snoitnetni tseb sih etipseD
.teef sih ot kcab tog ylwols neht ,niaga derekcins eloC  ".srewolf naht retteb yaw saw tahT“ .deddon xof ehT
ohw yug regit siht saw erehT“
htiw taht tnemelppus uoy fI .snoiger gnidnuorrus eht fo emos dna
weksa dekconk neeb dah lewot s'eloC taht
.xaler retteb ot sgel sih derewol d'eh nehw
.kcaba nekat saw eloC
lewot eht fo egde eht tfil ot swap htob desu eH .noitca elpmis a fo mrof eht ni emac rewsna sih ,oS .mih ot thgir
yojne esaelP   .emoh yrruh ot
W“  "?nigriv a llits er'uoy taht ssendrawkwa siht lla yb ti ekat I“  ".mH“  ".ekil
.citcat tnereffid a yrt ot dediced eH
,retnuocne laer tsal sih neeb dah
smoorhtab mrod eht ni ti gnioD
.dnim ot emac sevlow dednuow tuoba gniyas dlo eht tub
dna flow eht morf yawa noitnetta sih decrof eh
.ti yas flesmih ekam t'ndluoc eh "…er'uoy
".lairetam dneirfyob yltcaxe ton m'I tub ,dik ,etuc er'uoY“
.tuoba si siht tahw s'tahT .haey ,oS“
.gab myg sih hguorht degammur eh sa dias flow eht
"?gniod uoy era tahW“
edivorp ot dednetni erew slevel
.sedud ekil yletinifed I tub
.elims ymaerd a no tup surriS  "?retteb leeF“
.htgnel s'eloC gnola sregnif wef a dils ylregnig eh dna
.flesmih desseug dnoces eh sa edis sih ot kcab derewol ylraen ti
.esruoc sti ekat ot nageb erutaN
.tsael ta taht tuoba doog er'uoy ,haN“
.elissim gnikees kcid a ekil noitcere s'eloC no ni dekcol seye eulb 'surriS ,msagro nwo sih etipseD
.dehgual llits eH
,kcid nellows yrev sih ta nwod dekool surriS
.taht ot dnopser ot woh erus t'nsaw surriS
,pu naelc dik eht pleh ot lewot a rof dehcaer eloC .elzzum dna
yletelpmoc tlef surriS erus ekam ot hguone tsuj
.anuas eht ni ecneirepxe rieht morf
.taeh eht ot desu gnitteg tsuJ“
?ti dluohs ,rettam t'ndluohs
,sesiri eulb esoht htiw mih ta pu dekool surriS dna seye sih morf yawa rufdaeh s'xof eht fo emos hsurb ot wap a desu eH ".ti s'taht ,haeY
,revo saw ti nehW  .depolevne
.ylper eht otni gnihsur ,deganam eh ",haey-
.terces sih htiw
.gnihtyna naht erom xelfer fo tuo ti thguac ohw ,xof eht ta llor eht fo redniamer eht dessot eH ".ereH“
"…gnihtemos ro tuo og
.epahs sih ot ruotnoc yltcefrep ot demmirt neeb dah dnarts hcae fi sa tsomla saw tI .dezilaer xof eht
,ti od ylbaborp dluow skcil wef A
gnirats erew uoy ekil skool ti esuaC
flow ehT  ".oot ylenol m'I ebyam …tuB
suoucipsnoc rehtar a gnisuac
.niaga ekops eh sa enot retfos a no koot eciov s'flow ehT
revo dehsaw ria mraw fo sevaw elihw xaler ot gnitrats flesmih dnuof noos surriS dna
.ssentnulb no gnilttes erofeb sdrow txen sih esarhp ot tseb woh deredisnoc eloC
.yalpsid lluf no saw tonk sih dna
…gnihtemos ylsuoivbo saw erehT .efil lanosrep s'flow eht no
deffuh eloC  .gnikniht saw eh tahw yas ot woh fo erusnu
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ssalc oN ?syadnuS tuoba tahW“  ".esle
ti sa doog sa saw bojwolb tsrif s'xof eht erus gnikam no saw sucof laer sih ,llitS
.em no emit ruoy gnitsaw uoy tnaw t'ndluow I ,saw I fi dnA .dneirfyob a rof
.ffo saw ti dias dah eloC yaw eht tuoba gnihtemos dna mih no tsol t'nsaw "ytiurf“ drow eht fo gninaem elbuod ehT ?tahW ,tiaW
otni muc eh diD
sneppah tsuj ti ,wonk uoy
.dnim sih ot emac taht gniht tsrif eht dias tsuj eh ,ylper ot mih gnitcepxe saw flow eht gnizilaeR
deredisnoc eloC dna
"?zzum ruoy ni
,noitcere sih fo noitrop desopxe eht nwod sregnif wef a nar dna nwod dehcaer flow ehT ".reklat teews a uoy t'nerA“
.desaet gnieb saw eh taht noisserpmi tcnitsid eht dah surriS
?yas eh dluoc tahW  "?seirrebwarts
.ecaps lanosrep s'flow eht gnidavni saw eh ekil gnileef
.neht krow ro
.flesmih htiw desaelp yrev saw eh detseggus taht enot taht gnisu llits
,rof gnikool saw eh tahw dnuof flow ehT
"?uoy rof xesttub dna sbojwolb tsuj lla ti sI
.tops eros a otni gid ot tnaw t'nod I .eloC ,KO“
tnecsa sih deddon surriS
flesmih revo depard d'eh
".tey etad a no neeb neve t'nevah I
,elzzum sih morf muc tnanmer eht fo emos dekcil eH
.eson ruoy hguorht ehtaerb tsuJ“
.htaehs sih fo esab eht otni eson sih dediug neht
.elzzum sih depacse ti ecno
ni ti rof pu edam eh tub ,gniod saw eh tahw fo hcum nwonk evah ton yam xof ehT
delffur llits saw tI
.xamilc a ot xof eht ekat ot hcum ekat t'ndluow ti llet ydaerla dluoc flow ehT
R“ .ylper kaew a deganam neht ,dewollaws eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.setunim wef a rof tsael ta
.ssem a eb annog s'ti
.ti kaerb ot evitaitini eht koot surriS ,ecno roF
,loop eht ta syug gnilgo neeb dah eh fI
hgual tfos a
,eloC deman flow a
,wonk uoy …tuB .enif
,reilrae seye sih detreva dah eh hguohtlA
,kcab sih no saw eloC ,anuas eht ni kcaB
.spets llams wef a tsuj – meht neewteb ecnatsid eht dessorc flow ehT
.flow rehtona htiw moor mrod elttil ynit a erahs I .hctib ,em egduj t'noD
,noitapicitna fo naorg tfos a tuo tel eloC ,deilpmoc xof eht sA  ".lliks a s'tI
,dehcnilf surriS sa dna ,ecno wap a desiar eH
.xof eht dedrager eh sa seye s'flow eht nihtiw til erif suoregnad A
?rehto hcae wonk ot gnitteg tuoba woH“
.swalc sih fo skcab eht gnitcepsni erew eh fi sa ria toh eht otni pu wap a dleh eH .elkcuhc yhtaerb a tuo tel flow ehT
".em ot ecin ytterp sleef ti os ,tey yaw eht lla ni emoc t'nsah taoc retniw yM
s'taht dnA .taht lla dna dehcatta sgnirts on dias uoy wonk I ,eloC“
ti ot koot eh tub ,tsrif ta tfos oot saw tI
etalp reh no hguone dah ehS
,dooG“  .kcid s'eloC no doog yllaer tlef yllautca hcihw ,don a evag yllanif eh tub
.seye sih dellor surriS
"?tuo gnissim tuoba naem I tahw eeS“  ".retteb yaW .haeY“
dluoc eh tub ,flow eht morf gnimoc ssenkrad siht fo ekam ot tahw erus t'nsaw eH
,pley elttil rehtona tuo tel surriS
anuas eht morf degreme yeht ,yarps gnizirodoed emos htiw moor eht nwod gniyarps dna ffo gnilewot retfA
eloC tub ,gnitnioppasid saw tahT
,yas ot gniht diputs a hcus saw tI ".woW“
gnimmuc em htiw KO uoY .gnol ekat t'now ti ,em tsurT .tirips eht s'taht ,heH“  .kcab llup t'ndid eh ,tiderc sih ot tub ,deworran seye s'xof ehT  ".elzzum ruoy kcuf annog tsuj m'I os ,ffo teg ot deen yllaer
.dexif eb ot sdeen taht gniht nekorb emos ton m'I .surriS ,kooL“
elihw tonk gnillews yldipar s'enipluv eht etalumits yltneg ot nageb dna
.semitemos loop eht ta syug ta kool uoy yaw eht nees ev'I
.uoy rof hcum oot s'ti fi nwod ti nrut nac I .mH“  ".taeh
?taht tuoba erus uoY“
.egde eht revo surriS gnirb ot troffe hcum ekat t'ndid ti ,stcnitsni s'eloC ot eurT  .reverof tnemom taht ni evil tsuj ot yppah neeb evah dluow surriS dna
.gnilaeppa elttil a naht erom …saw mih dnuora depparw htuom mraw a fo aedi eht ,timda ot dah eH
.gnikool doog ytterp er'uoy ezilaer attog ev'uoY ?yhW“  ".desirprus
.esoprup no neeb t'ndah ti
.daeh sih dniheb sdnah sih deppils eh sa dehgis eloC  "?eb I dluohS“
.won thgir uoy wolb ll'I
"?haey ,sgniht esoht neewteb gnihtemos od attog uoy
.anuas eht fo taeh dekan eht ot noitcere sih desopxe ylwols dna
".si siht tahw erus ton m'I
.pirg nwo sih esaeler ot euc sih sa ti koot eloC dna
-hw detpurretnI“  ".dekconk
noitisop taht morf level eye woleb tsuj saw ezag siH
boj elbarimda na gniod dna
,pit sti ot pu desserac neeb noos dah kcid
,llew …dnA .od ot retteb gnihton dah I dna ,thgin eht fo dne eht saw tI
pu ti dellor tsuj neht
fo kniht ot gniyrt yletarepsed elihw stnemtsujda wef a edam
erawa emaceb surriS ,stnemom gnol esoht gnirud tniop emos tA
"?syob tuoba klaT
"?nwot dnuora syug yag
.shtnom xis rof rehtegot dekrow ev'eW
.mraw saw 'surriS sa dloc sa saw rewsna s'eloC
.yhtapme erom elttil a nommus ot flesmih decrof eh os ,sdrow fo eciohc s'flow eht yb ffo tup elttil a saw eh llet dluoc eloC  .egakcap eht fo tuo eno dellup neht ,seidnac eht ta deffins surriS ".KO ,haey …tuB
…fo tol a ereht erA
.niaga dehgual eh sa tib a nihc sih detfil eloC
.sgel s'flow eht neewteb nagro eht ot
,deddon flow ehT  ".era
gnihtyna naht retteb yletinifed saw ti tub
uoy peews emoc ot yob yag ylecnirp emos rof gnitiaw peek uoy fi
kcoc sih fo trap eht dnuora gnipparw ydaerla sregnif suoretxed sih
.thgiew erom yrrac ot ti rof dednetni d'eh ekiL
.ahsirT saw dlot reve d'eh nosrep ylno ehT
.hteet fo elpuoc a neewteb ti dleh eh sa dias eh ".dooG“
.hcneb eht fo tuo gnisir tserdaeh ralugnairt a no pu depporp daeh sih
,retsaf gnitteg taebtraeh ruoy raeh nac I“  "?tahw-W“
.meht ot tuo emoc t'nevah I nosaer a s'ereht dna
.eciov gnikaeps lamron sih gnisu etipsed moor eht hguorht ylduol gniohce enotirab sih
.htrim fo lluf seye dlog sih ,niaga mih ta gnikool saw eloC  ".semitemos
lacitpeks dednuos eloC
ecitcarp morf neeb dah selcsum sih fo emos eros woh dezilaer t'ndah eH
surriS   ".yadot uoy rof drawkwa oot t'nsaw gniht yadhtrib taht epoh I“
,niaga taht od ot tnaw uoy fI
.gnihtemos dedeen I ?xof ,tnaw uoy od tahW“
.ekil leef dluow siht ekil gnihtemos tahw derednow d'eh
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
".drazzilb a gnirud ekorts taeh uoy evig ot deganam I fi diputs ytterp leef d'I
.suoivbo erom ti ekam ot flow eht sdrawot swap htob htiw derutseg eh ",siht …naem I“
.tseb syawla s'tahT .mm …s'taht
?maS dlot dah ehs elbissop ti saw
.snoitseuq fo tol a ksa uoy ,tsirhc gnikcuf suseJ“
kcab ti ekat ot etal oot saw ti tub
.reilrae tnemom a neve dah ti naht
.ydob s'flow eht enimaxe ot
".noitasrevnoc laer a dah reve ev'ew emit tsrif eht si sihT
.esle hcum rof emit evah t'noD
…I“  ".kool taht wonk I tub ,edih ot ysae ti sekam gniht draugefil ehT
siht ni od ot gniht drawkwa na eb thgim ti thguoht eh tub ,sdeen nwo sih fo erac gnikat yldipar
,efil sih fo xamilc tseb eht yltcaxe t'nsaw tI
,seye s'flow eht otni ylpeed dekool surriS
.s'xof eht fo eno fo pot no ffo flesmih kcaj ot gnisu neeb d'eh wap eht decalp ylpmis dna
.nirg lufyalp a won noisserpxe sih ,deggurhs flow ehT
,yltnatcepxe mih ta gnikool llits saw xof eht gnieeS ".snoitseuq
sgniht rehto tog s'ehs ,llew …tub
.nac uoy fI .sgnaf ruoy gniparcs morf em peek ot pil reppu dna eugnot ruoy esU
.yenom reh rof nur a reh evig ot elba eb ll'uoY
.wap gnikcaj sih fo evaw evissimsid a surriS evag eloC
sah ohw ,ryC rohtarB yb ”maetS“
.ytiniffAruF dna
.pit eht morf gnikeep nageb der fo owt ro hcni na
.dekconk tsrif uoy nehw
wap deyalps a decalp eloC
fo trap lanif dna
.ffo gnikrej nettog evah dluow eh
?tuo gnah t'nac ew naem
.erofeb mih morf draeh dah surriS gnihtyna naht tsenrae erom saw txen ekops eh yaw ehT
.hguone eb dluow tI
,tnemom a rof suoires emaceb noisserpxe
,rekrowoc modnar emos dlot dah ehs fI
.pu hctac ot deirt eh sa yldipar gnipmup
ot detnaw reve uoy fi
.llaf ti tel naht rehtar wap eno htiw desolc ti dloh ot dah eh ,dne eht nI
.sessalc sih fo eno ni tem dah eloC raeb ralop ydren siht htiw snoisses noitabrutsam lautum wef a rof gnivas
.elihw a neeb d'tI
".ti tnaw uoy fi ti od ot gniog
s'flow eht ,yojne ot demees surriS hcihw ,mucerp gnizoo ni derevoC
.trihs sih no gnillup dehsinif eh sa mih ta kcab kool neve t'ndid flow ehT
.mih ni kcid fo sehcni ruof ro eerht tsuj htiw gag ot detrats
.mom ym tsuj s'tI“  ".yson
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,tiaW“  ".emit eht lla tuo syug kcehc ot ereh emoc ot desu I .lla ta toN“
.nialpmoc ot tuoba t'nsaw
.gniht lausac fo dnik siht“
,tonk s'flow eht gnippirg ni euqinhcet s'eloC derorrim surriS ,xamilc gnidnepmi eht gnisneS
?mih gnillet saw ydob sih tahw ot netsil ot
,dootsrednu xof eht ton ro rehtehW
eht "?epacse ruoy gninnalp ydaerlA“  ".melborp
tcere meht fo eno nees reven d'eh tub
drawrof spih sih thguorb eh sa
waj rewol s'flow eht morf noitcetorp gnidda
.mom sih saw ereht neht dnA .omoh a
.skcil tfiws wef a htiw
.rehtaew dab ot eud emoh edir a teg ot
,naem I …tsuJ .gnihtoN“
.htuom sih otni tnim eht deppils eh sa tcatnoc eye gnidiova ,nwod dekool surriS
,deretsulf mih peek ot stpmetta s'flow eht revo nettog yllanif d'eh thguoht dah surriS
htiw moor rekcol a gnirahs eldnah ot elba eb dluow maS ekil enoemos gnikniht emit drah a dah eH
.dnuora kcab denrut eh sa ezag s'eloC teem ot denruter yeht tub
.heH“  ".hO“ .noitseuq nwo sih ot rewsna eht dezilaer eh sa ffo flesmih tuc surriS "-
debborht kcoc sih sa
.tuo sgniht erugif ot drah
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,epip gnorw eht nwod enog dah muc emoS
.stnim htaerb paehc fo llor a
,seye ediw htiw gnihctaw saw xof ehT
gnisuma taht dnif ot demees eloC
.htaehs s'flow eht fo pot eht tuo ekam tsuj dluoc eh
tonk sih ot pu dik eht koot neht ,htaerb peed a tcelloc ot hguone gnol kcoc 'surriS ffo gnillup yb noitaraperp tsal eno edam eloC
.daeh sih koohs surriS
,ytiC aceneS ot pirt lanoisacco eht dna tihs enilno
,god.ecioveht ta
.lacitpeks llits saw xof ehT
,llits yletelpmoc gnidloh tuohtiw eganam dluoc eh sa wols sa tuoba gniog ydaerla saw
…ti tel tsuj eh did ro ,did surriS ekil seussit
.kaep sih ot teg ot etunim a tuoba eloC koot ylno tI
,tfahs kciht s'enipluv eht deldarc eugnot siH
.sraey ytnewt ylraen rof noitcif yrruf citore gnitirw neeb
.etib t'ndluow I uoy dlot I“
.tsiaw sih dnuora eit ylreporp ot mih rof gib oot tib a saw ti hguohtla
.rufdaeh 'surriS no
,eson sih raen elzzum sih fo edis eht deppat eh
,demoorg-llew ylsuolucitem osla saw ruf siH
.amora tnasaelp s'eloC htiw gnilgnim ,esnetni erom werg yletaidemmi lasuora sih fo tnecs ehT
.yad gnol eht retfa doog tlef tI .mih
".xof ,oot uoy kcuF“
.tihs hguot s'eh skniht eh ylneddus dna bojwolb eno yug a eviG
?knarp a siht saW
.mih deliaf dah noitanigami siH
.eulb eci tem sesiri dlog dna
,meht neewteb dessap taht ecnelis drawkwa eht ekorb flow eht ,os ro etunim a retfA
hcuot thgim taht gnihtyna fo tuo dekcab eh os
.deen sih yevnoc yletarucca dluow sdrow tahw erus neve t'nsaw eH .yltcerid
.denigami reven d'eh yaw a ni mih dednuorrus taeh dna
,daeh s'xof eht fo kcab eht no
naht saw ti reggib hcum woh riaf t'nsaw tI
.pop elbidua na htiw kcoc sih desaeler eloC
tae nac uoy lla eht ot tekcit eerf a uoy gnivig m'I
wap a esiar ot deganam llits eh ,nohtaram a nur tsuj d'eh fi sa dekool eh hguoht dna ,dehsulf surriS
.rekcol ffats a ni sgnignoleb sih fo tsom dehsats dna nwod deppirts dah eh
erofeb delbmum eh ",ti kcuF“
.regnif eht mih evig dna
s'flow ehT  "?em fo nuf gnikam uoy erA“
ekil kool thgim flow eht tahw tuoba detaluceps eh sa
".kool yletinifed uoy tuB
.nagro digrut eht ot eson sih derewol dna
s'tI“ .ti yas dluohs eh fi erus t'nsaw xof eht tub
.tuo em gnikcehc erew uoy derugif I
.yson teg yeht fi htaerb ruoy no muc llems t'nod stnerap ruoy erus ekam ll'tahT“
.tuoba kniht ot driew …s'tahT“  ".yenom
.weiv retteb a uoy gniviG“
.elzzum evissap s'flow eht no saw sucof sih hguoht
?swalc s'rehto hcae tniap
?hsirT ta kool sedud woh wonk uoY
.yas ot tahw tuo erugif ot deirt eh sa sgnaf sih fo eno htiw pil mottob sih no nwod erob surriS
.mih ta derats tsuj surriS  .desaet flow
yrev tlef siht taht saw wonk did eh tahW
gnikool ton m'I tuB
ylno m'I …tsuJ .siht yojne htob d'ew kniht I dna
.dedicednu saw eH
.elims lufyalp a xof eht evag neht
,flesmih dnuora depparw wap a dah eh ,xof eht morf ecnatsissa yna gnitcepxe toN
,elzzum sih desu eloC sa nevE .msaisuhtne
.taorht s'flow eht nwod gnipmup nageb muc ytlas ,niht dna
erats did surriS
".seirrebwarts ekil setsaT“
flow eht nioj ot sediced xof eht
.mucerp fo tib a etiuq
.eciov dna enot ni htob ,egde deggar a no koot sdrow siH
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
level rehtona ot sgniht koot neht flow ehT
noitseuq ni htaehs eht taht xof eht no tsol t'nsaw tI
.srood tnorf eht dehcaorppa yeht sa taht redisnoc ot demees flow ehT
.ffo xof eht deppord d'eh retfa
derednow surriS taht hguone wols saw gnihtaerb sih dna
,sdrow eht ta der fo edahs peed a denrut srae s'xof ehT
.ytterp erew seye sih ,kcuF .derevihs eloC
".uoy rof ereht eb
,rekrowoc gnitadimitni na hcaorppa ot decrof saw ,xof citcra na ,surriC ,emit tsaL
.tey hcaer t'ndluoc elzzum sih
.mih rof tluciffid sgniht ekam yletinifed dluow ti ,tuo dnuof maet eht fI
"?anuas eht yhw oS“
.reilrae stnemom wef a noitcere sih laecnoc ot gnisu neeb dah xof eht lewot eht ta gnippirg llits saw tI
,sgel s'flow eht neewteb detfird seye sih sA
rehtegot ti dloh dluoc surriS fi saw tahT
.ta gnitteg saw eh tahw raelc ti gnikam
.yawllah eht otni tuo deppets yeht sa dewollof surriS dna
thgim I tuB .yrt ot gnilliw m'I“
".em ot ralupop ytterp mees uoY ?haeY“
,uoy no erusserp fo tol a gnittup m'I wonk I ,kooL“
".yaw taht ti ekil I ebyaM“
.gnikcil nageb dna ,tnih eht koot xof ehT
.elzzum sih deppid xof ehT  ".etuc ytterp
.sessalc ot og dna krow I“
.sleef ti woh no etartnecnoc tsuj ,hcum oot kniht ot ton yrT
fo ylppus ydaets a s'ereht
.tnemevom decitcarp-llew tub luferac a htiw
naem thgim ti tahw tuoba deirrow eh ,niagA
,remraw eb ot saw detnaw eh gniht tsal eht
?ffo dekrej eh nehw ekil kool ti did tahW
er'uoY ?wonk uoy ,gnirettalf fo dnik s'ti ,naem I .eruS“  "?yllaer-
.bur a rufdaeh s'xof eht evag neht ,dehgis eH
etarebiled erew stnemevom siH
.eciov 'surriS ni esor enot citehtapmys A
".pu dekrow ytterp er'uoy llet nac I
?sih naht regral hcum taht s'eloC saW .nosrep ni
.tuo dnuof dah rekrowoc sih wohemos tuB
.edurp a tsuj er'uoy ebyaM“
siht ekil dneterp
,tuhs htuom sih tpek eloC dna flow eht morf yawa dekool dna smra sih dessorc surriS  ".etuc s'tahT“
dna ereh fo tuo klaw ot tnaw tsuj uoy fi KO s'ti os
siht ekil stnemom tuoba dezisatnaf
.nuf ekil sdnuos taht ,recin elttil a ecalpemos pukooh neve ebyam ro
.dlrow eht ni noitautis lausac tsom eht erew ti fi sa detca
tixe eht sdrawot gniklaw detrats
,nwo sih naht rekciht tol a demees tI
.htuom sih otni ti deppop neht ,kcats eht morf ydnac pot eht deleep dna repparw eht nepo erot eh ,walc a gnisU
,meht fo owt eht neewteb regnif xedni na devaw eh
.seiromem eht yb deripsni yltnerappa ,htaehs sti morf dednetxe ylluf dah kcoc s'flow ehT  ".yltcaxe toN“
,srood eht pu kcol ot tnemom a koot flow ehT
.hsiugnal noitasrevnoc rieht tel ot tnetnoc demees ylniatrec eH .ffo dezod dah eh fi
.daeh sih koohs eh dna
…tsuj m'I .tuo depeerc ton m'I“  ".yawyna
".tnaw uoy fi gnimrahc ecnirp fo kniht dna seye ruoy esolC
drawrof denael eloC
.esle gnihtyreve derewoprevo noos tnim eht tub
,kcen 'surriS fo esab eht ta
.htgnel eritne s'surriS gnola eugnot kcils ,talf eht werd ylwols neht
".taht ot yas ot tahw wonk neve t'nod I“
,deggurhs flow ehT
.drawkwa erom sgniht ekam ylniatrec dluow ti tub ,gnihtyna ro maet eht ffo mih kcik d'yeht detbuod eH
tol gnikrap derevoc-wons eht ssorca deklaw yeht neht
.noisserpxe napdaed a flow eht
.slewot sih fo eno barg ot spets wef a kcab deklaw eh sa seye sih dellor eloC
"?thgir ,oot od uoY
.ekil uoy si ti revetahw ro ssa ro kcid
,anuas moor rekcol eht ni mih sdnif surriC retfA
mih erusserp naht rehtar
,gnihtoos saw ruf sih tsniaga cirbaf etihw yffulf eht fo htmraw ehT
,ryC rohtarB yb ”maetS“
.emoh ta hsurb a esu
.tuo gnihtemos krow nac ew sseug I“
"?wonk uoy ,gnihtemos naem ot emit tsrif
"?ecalp tseb eht saw krow ta anuas eht dediced uoy ,yllarutan ,oS“
gnorw yllaer ti saW .semit derdnuh a
.elzzum rednels eht otni kcid sih dils neht
eugnot sih htiw htgnel s'flow eht gnildarc ylluferac saw surriS
,s04 etal sih ni ylbaborp ekil – dlo fo dnik saw eH .ssap yad enO
moor eht fo tser eht no desucof xof eht ,daetsnI
,niaga suoicsnoc-fles gnileef trats ot sesnes sih fo hguone deniager dah surriS dna
,gniog tpek dna seye sih desolc tsuj eh os
.eno egnarts a saw ti ,ekoj a saw ti fI
,ecaf s'xof eht fo edis eht no mlap evitatnet a ecalp ot pu dehcaer eloC
.rekihhctiH flowereW
flesmih dewolla surriS
siht lla tuoba ot klat ot enoemos esu yllaer dluoc I ,si tniop yM“  ".kcid
,flesmih revoc ot gnisu neeb d'eh lewot eht ta deggut yllausac eloC
uoy ekil od I tub
A“  .mih tuoba yrrow ot gnivah tuohtiw
.niaga ekops flow eht erofeb tnemom a rof deregnil tnemmoc ehT ".etib
.ton esruoc fo-O ?!tahW“  ".em ta
loohcs dnuora tog ti fi
.ecnelis ni desserd gnitteg detrats yeht
ecap retsaf ylthgils a ta nwod dna pu elzzum s'xof eht gnidiug ydaerla saw eloC ".tseb
ytnuoc eritne eht morf ni sklof sgnirb egelloc ytinummoc eht tub ,tol a toN“
",htiw elbatrofmoc m'I dna ,ma I tahw htiw elbatrofmoc m'I
.retteb yaw od nac uoY
,yhtrae na ria eht evag ti ,rehtegoT
,dluoc eh fi ,pleh ot saw tcnitsni 'surriS .ereht lufniap
.enips s'xof eht pu srevihs tnes taht
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,seye deworran htiw kool gnisiarppa na mih evag ,niaga pu tas eloC
eno siht piks esaelp
t'nsi siht ,ekatsim on ekaM“
– moor eht fo taeh eht etipsed dloc wohemos llits – eson sih gnisserp erofeb avilas fo
,tnemmoc ssarc eht yb truh saw surriS
.ni ytidun s'elam regnuoy eht koot eh sa dehtaerb flow eht
.noitapicitna ni spil sih dekcil eloC dna
,gniht fo dnik taht dekil uoy dias hsirT tub ,em rof ytiurf oot tib A ?haeY“
.mih dlot evah tsum ahsirT
taht seoD .setad on ,KO“ .tnih a ekat
ytnelp gnitareneg saw htuom sih erus edam eH
esoht tuoba gnikniht llitS
.ria eht ni ti llems dluoc surriS .roolf eht otno ti fo emos
tsuj ot tnetnoc yllausu saw surriS .evisnepxe yrev erew yeht tub
.ereht nwod eb ot drawkwa tlef ti ,revo saw tca eht
.hcaorppa sih ta gnitlob morf lamina llams emos peek ot gniyrt erew eh fi sa ,wols tub
".dnim t'nod I .KO s'tI“
,taerg si hsirT
.oga shtnom wef a ereh hguorht emac
"?taht yas uoy od yhW“
,lewot sih fo tnorf eht tsniaga gnisserp lasuora nwo sih tlef eh litnu
?em gnisaet uoy era-
.dessarrabme saw eh nehw tog eciov sih dehctip hgih woh detah eH ".ton
"…ffo skrej su fo eno fi dna ,yb emoc ot drah s'ycavirP
".snoisacco laiceps rof dnuora stelbat enimorboeht-itna wef a peek I tub
,yldlrowrehto saw sihT
".doog saw ekac ehT .KO
.eb ylbissop dluoc
.hguorht neeb tsuj d'eh tahw morf
.tsehc sih ot kcab wap sih gnirewol ylwols
xof ehT .erac ot desuora oot saw flow eht tub ,mih fo etsat a teg did hteet 'surriS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
dah eh taht yned t'ndluoc eh tub ,mih rednu morf tuo gur eht dellup dah flow eht ,seY
.reilrae em gnivig erew uoy kool emas eht em gnivig tpek eh tub
.thgis fo enil s'xof eht otni kcab
.tihs krowemoh dna gniyduts ym fo tsom od I nehw s'tahT“  ".neht
,niaga gnirats saw eh dezilaer eh erofeB
,detseretni er'uoy fi ,naem I“
sdnah sih otno nettog dah ti fo sdnarts yarts wef a
,yaw taht ti fo kniht ot ekil yllaer t'nod I ,naem I .sseug I
.ton esruoc fO .oN“
nac I ,em morf gnihtyna deen reve uoy fi dnA .ffuts yag
.yawyna ,sgniht esoht ton ,lleW“
,wols htiw flesmih ekorts ot deunitnoc flow eht sa gnihctaw morf flesmih pots ot elba neeb t'ndah surriS
,gnihtemos ro evol
.denoihsaf dlo erew yeht dna ,pissog ot dekil ereh elpoep ehT .nwot eht ro
rettoh werg skeehc 'surriS dna
kcid sih thguorb siht ,yllatnedicnI
eht ",yug etalocohc a fo erom m'I sseug I“
erehw srekcol ffats eht ot yaw rieht edam dna
ylivaeh gnihtaerb niaga ecno
,haeY ?rekcuskcoc A“
,dlrow nwo sih ni eb ot demees eloC taht won
regniferof dna bmuht sih htiw gnir a demrof flow eht ,nemodba rewol sih no
.ecnelis eht ekorb eh ,yllaniF .txetnoc
".dael eht ekat em tel retteB
.lluf htuom ruoy htiw klat ot drah ytterp eb annog s'ti tuB
".krans ekil setsaT“
.nael did eh hguohtla
eugnot sih no gniregnil eb ylekil dluow taht enipluv fo etsat eht gnirovas
,ffo deliart eH "…ot uoy deen
.xof eht ot noitnetta lluf sih evag niaga ecno dna flesmih gnikorts deppots flow ehT
.pu nepO .xof ,KO“
.gnileef taht rebmemer I ,haeY“ .dehgis eloC
.dehgis neht ,deppots eH "—uoy od tahW“  ".lluf
mih morf yawa nettog dah sthguoht sih ezilaer neve t'ndid eH
.noituloser a hcaer ot demees eh ,yllaniF
mih ta pu delims xof ehT
".gnihtemos ekab ot detnaw yllaer ehs kniht I dna
.gnineve eht fo tser eht rof
"?ton yhW“  "?taht od d'uoY“
.piy a dna naom a neewteb erehwemos saw taht esion egnarts a htiw flesmih detpurretni surriS "—I .eloC .kcuf ,hO“
,denruter elims siH ".uoy
.elcarim a tcepxe ton s'tel ,haeY“
,em tuoba yrrow ot deen t'ndid uoy uoy dlot I“
.ytisoiruc luftsul ot yaw evag noos ssenyhs dna ylkciuq
reh detsurt d'eH ?eloC dlot evah hsirT dluoW .flow eht draeh ylerab surriS
"?ereh ni enoemos dekcuf uoy ,dog ym hO“  ".deneppah sgniht
Y“  ".teiuq ytterp mees uoY ?surriS ,KO uoY“
tnemesuma sih kcab dleh eloC  "…t'nac-c I“
".nwot elohtihs siht ni nevE
eloC .tnemevom yreve ta gnisnet saw xof eht ,ecivda s'eloC etipseD
,flesmih ot noitnetta llac ot ton gniyrT .eglub
…tsuJ .gnihton s'tI .on …hU“
.kcid fo stoL .eruS“ .dekrens eloC
.nruter on fo tniop eht
.uoy rof redrah sgniht ekam si od annaw I gniht tsaL .enif s'taht ,tuo uoy gnipeerc s'ti fI .emit txen
.srebif eht fo emos detarutas ydaerla mucerp siH
,hcneb sih no kcab denael xof ehT
evag eh ,enod saw eh nehW
,noitcerid sih ni worbeye na desiar eloC
.niaga mih deliaf sdrow sih tub
,secaps yrruf ynam ni seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.edud kcuf ,naem I“
,em wonk yllaer sdneirf ym kniht t'nod I .yllaer toN“
"?enoyna htiw dnuora deloof uoy evaH“  "?tahw-
.sredluohs sih otno kcap yvaeh sih decalper eh sa deggurhs surriS
"?taht uoy dlot ohW“
.ecivda emos tuo dehtaerb eh ,tsehc s'xof eht ot eson sih gnirewoL
surriS ot denoitnem d'eh regit taht ,hturt nI
ym tnaw tsuj I .edurp a ton m'I“  ".edurp
,seninac rof dab s'ti ,wonk I“  .dias flow
seno doog tsael tA
dekcil neht dessik dna
.egde eht revo mih yrrac wam mraw s'surriS dna erusaelp fo evaw eht tel dna llits dleh tsuj neht ,lrans wol a tuo tel ,rethgit daeh 'surriS deppirg flow ehT .dedeen eh erehw eloC teg ot hguone saw erusserp neddus eht ,drah oot tib
,meht neewteb dessap teiuq fo tnemom A
seitinutroppo fo tol a no tuo ssim ot gniog er'uoy tub ,msilaedi ruoy peek ot gnorw er'uoy yas ot gniog ton m'I
.loohcs hgih emas eht ot tnew eW
.melborp a eb ot ti rof hguone gnol ereh ni eb ll'ew tbuod I .KO s'taht ,oN“
.citelhta ylraelc saw eh tub ,redliub ydob on saw eH