.dexaler flow eht erofeb sdnoces lareves rof surriS no dexif saw ezag tahT
.gnirats neeb d'eh gnizilaer neht ylno ,deganam surriS ",haey-
.reffo reh no pu god eht koot tsomla surriS os
ehT "?won emoh gnidaeh uoY“
sih fo kcab eht debbur flow ehT  .deddon surriS
,emoh og saw od ot detnaw eh llA
.dekconk dah surriS nehw nwod gniyal neeb dah eh raelc ti edam taht yaw a ni
.thginot pu gnisolc s'eloC kniht I“  .dekrep liat reh
.ffats gnineve eht fo tser eht htiw tuo gnah ot looc oot saw eh gnikniht mih sa taht deterpretni tsuj dah surriS
",yrruh on s'erehT“
,emit ot emit morf yrdnual eht htiw depleh surriS .esu rebmem rof slewot derednual ylhserf fo noitcelloc a dah moor rekcol hcaE
",mih ot klat ll'I .thgin lla ereh gnittis naht retteb s'ti ,lleW“
,noitisop detaes a ot kcab detfihs eh ,yllaudarG
elbatrofmoc tlef hsirT ssel eht
xof ehT  .naelc tpek erew yeht gnirusne tuoba
.lausac dednuos depoh eh taht enot a ni dias eh ",sknahT“  ".ecnahc
.emac rewsna s'flow eht erofeb stnemevom kciuq wef a was surriS ,ssalg detsorf eht hguorhT
rof reh htiw sdneirf neeb dah surriS dna hsirT gnitad saw maS esuaceb smret doog no erew yeht tub ,esolc yrev t'nerew meht fo owt ehT
,wolg tniaf a dah syawla ehs ekil kool reh edam ruf nedlog reh tuoba gnihtemoS
.ralupop os saw ehs rednow on saw tI
.srood renni eht hguorht kcab deklaw neht
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.srezirodoed dna stcudorp gninaelc fo ylgnorts gnillems
,dias tahT .rehtegot ytud draugefil dah d'yeht nehw yllaicepse
.gnorts erew ereh stnecs eht ,tnasaelpnu yleritne ton elihW
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.pu em gnikcip s'maS .surriS ,yrroS“
htiw emit gnidneps
.enilno dnuof ehs epicer a gnisu
"yadhtriB yppaH“ fo noitidner yek-ffo na hguorht yaw rieht elgnub ot llew wonk t'ndid uoy elpoep fo puorg a rof gnitiaW
,tuo yaw reh no guh kciuq a xof eht evag ehs ,daetsnI
,ryC rohtarB yb ”maetS“
,loohcs ta yad gnol a neeb dah tI
.gnimlehwrevo tsomla saw s'eloC
dnuora pu evil uoY“ .deredisnoc eloC
.srood tnorf eht ot pu dellup rac a nehw saw tahT
.revewoh ,aedi eht dessimsid noos eH
.niaga htrof dna kcab gnigniws liat
,krowemoh ym no trats ylrae na teg nac I .eruS“
.tsom naht retteb dloc rettib eht eldnah dluoc eh tnaem hcihw
.moor eht denil taht sehcneb nedoow dereit eht fo eno no
.noisnepsus degnolorp a gniwollof
.yad eht fo tsom rof
eciwt nroh sih depeeb revird ehT
.dniheb raewrednu sih gnivael sterger surriS fi ees ot emit txen ni enuT
smoor rekcol s'bulc eht fo hcae ,smyg redlo fo tol a ekiL .saw eloC erehw raelc emaceb ylkciuq ti
,tnew ytilacisyhp eht sa raf sa tuo dewollem dah flow derruf-kcalb eht ,syad esehT
.yrtne loop eht fo noitcerid eht ni yleugav derutseg eloC ".ereh
.evael ot gniraperp ylraelc
,tsiaw sih dnuora rethgit ti gnikcut ,lewot sih detsujda flow ehT
.aera loop eht tfel tahT
,revewoh ,dab saw rehtaew eht nehW
.ronaemed ylbbub lausu reh morf detalfed ylbisiv dah dna
.revewoh ,mih ees ot elba gnieb ton srac gnimocno
.niaga etal gninnur s'moM ,haN“
,rood eht sdrawot ylsuoixna dekool ahsirT dna
,reilrae syad wef a neeb yllautca dah yadhtrib htneethgie siH  ".ytrap
ereh kcuts eb ot gniog ylekil saw eh dna skeew ni thgin yadirF eerf tsrif siH
.noitnetta fo retnec eht gnieb elbatrofmoc reven saw eh tub ,thguoht eht detaicerppa xof ehT
?moor thgiew eht yrt ebyaM
.gniggaw liat reh ,deksa bal
,erots yrecorg eht morf sekac teehs denword-ragus esoht fo eno gnitteg morf srehto eht tpek dah ,tsael ta ,hsirT
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
eno siht piks esaelp
,sthgin ymrots no ylralucitrap
,pal sih ssorca depard yldrazahpah lewot a rof tpecxe edun saw eH
.enituor thgin-fo-dne lausu reh – rettulc yna fo raelc saw ksed eht erus gnikam dna
.was I tsal pu sgniht gnisolc saw eH
.sgnaf sih neewteb morf gnidurtorp
.semit fo elpuoc a dekconk xof eht
,ryC rohtarB yb ”maetS“
metsys retupmoc noitpecer eht nwod gnittuhs saw ,dneirf tseb sih ,ahsirT
,egelloc ot ffo derahs d'yeht rac eht nekat dah rehtorb redlo sih ecnis revE
.struoc llabteuqcar dna llabteksab eht desolc dah flesmih surriS
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
"?thgir ,nadirehS
.ecnahc a tog reven I tub ,yad lla yadhtrib yppah yas ot gninaem neeb ev'I“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,ecnelis fo sdnoces wef a retfa daeh sih detlit flow ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
.eugael llabteksab 'sdik lacol eht rof eerefer a sa gnitca sruoh eerht rehtona tneps d'eh neht dna
.sruoh wef a eb ot gniog ylbaborP
,eloC  .eno esnetni na saw ti tub ,noitasnes emoclewnu na yltcaxe t'nsaw tI
mih dniheb hcneb eht no tuo dial erom owt dna
.noitseggus taht ta nworf a kcab thguof surriS
.tnemom a rof noitseggus s'ahsirT gniredisnoc retfa dias eH
.rehtegot owt dna owt tup
.deppid liat reh dna deretlaf elims reh ,sdnoces wef a retfa tub deeps pu dekcip liat reH
.surriS ot ssorg fo dnik demees syawla smoor eht ,hturt nI
– ynnuf yllautca dna
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.tekcaj namrettel sih otni enohp sih deppils ylluferac xof citcra ehT  2 fo 1 traP
.ereh ni tuo gnignah ekil leef uoy fi slewot naelc fo ytnelp s'erehT
.noitarbelec lacipyt erom a rof thgin txen eht rehtegot teg ot snalp dah ,hsirT gnidulcni ,puorg dneirf sih dna eH
,flow eht eltrats ot gnitnaw toN
.tnemeerga sa koot surriS hcihw
.kcapkcab sih gnitsujda ylsuoicsnocnu
.ytilanosrep elbatirri na dna
anuas a dedulcni
.enog si esle enoyreve retfa tuo krow ot sekil eh kniht I
.ti tuoba yrrow t'noD“ .dennirg surriS
.llaretfa ,sdik loohcs hgih yltsom erew yehT
".regnol elttil a taeh eht yojne ot ecin eb dluow ti os ,gnol yrev ereh ni neeb t'nevah I“
ot evol I woh wonk uoY“
.eganam dluoc eh sa gnol sa rof
loohcs remmus ta raey lanif sih hsinif ot decrof neeb dah flow eht ,tcaf nI
er'uoy fi ,naem I“
.yad eht fo dne eht ta meht gninaelc eldnah ot dengissa yllausu saw eloC dalg saw dna
,ryC rohtarB yb
.sraey ytnewt ylraen rof noitcif yrruf citore gnitirw neeb sah ohw
tnemtnioppasid sih no pu dekcip bal nedlog eht ,yreehc eb ot troffe 'surriS etipseD  .egassem gnorw eht gnidnes diova ylevitca ot hguone mih otni saw hsirT desseug eh dna
hgis flesmih tel surriS taht tfel dah ehs retfa ylno saw tI
.yek-wol sgniht peek ot tnetnoc saw eh ,esiwrehtO
– raey eht fo mrotswons rojam tsrif eht – sekalfwons etihw gnitfird fo edacsac eht ta deralg eh sa tuB
.nwo sih no stohs ycnaf gnikat naht sseccus rof pu srehto gnittes tuoba erom saw taht noitisop a deyalp eh taht depleh tI
eht – ereh ni saw ti toh woh gniredisnoc gnisirprus t'nsaw tahT
.seussi rehto niatrec dna sseneros elcsum htiw pleh ot dednetni saw taht
.sgnineve tsom ta dekrow eh bulc citelhta eht dna loohcs morf dna ot teg ot ekib sih no deiler yltsom dah surriS
,stekcop sih otni swap sih deppils eh ,gnihgiS
,tuo sthgil eht lla htiw ypeerc tib a saw bulc ehT
"?uoy htiw edir a teg dluoc I esop's t'noD
.liat sih htiw skcilf wef a deganam neve dna taebpu dnuos ot eciov sih decrof eH ".hO“  ".krow
taht ria dimuh ,toh fo evaw a htiw deteerg saw xof eht
.emoh pirt eht ekam dluoc eh rehtehw gnirednop
,ffuts sih hsats dna sserdnu ot moor rekcol eht ot denruter surriS sA  ".erus ,haeY .hO“
.sthgif otni gnitteg rof noitatuper a depoleved dah ,roines a neht
dias ehs ",surriS ,yeH“
.kaerb rennid sih gnirud
Y“  "?thgirla gnihtyrevE“
ylkciuq surriS dna
desirprus demees eloC
.sedisnwod sti dah ti tub ,kool mih edam ruf etihw sih emosdnah woh mih gnillet syawla erew slriG
gnidulcni ,secaps yrruf ynam ni seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,emaceb pihsnoitaler rieht suoires erom eht ,revewoH
"?uoy taht sI ?eloC ,yeH“
.derit saw eH .ylbidua
”maetS“   yojne esaelP
.tsehc dna smra sih ni erutalucsum nael eht fo noitinifed eht ees ot reisae saw ti
.ruf foorpretaw sih no mrof ot noitasnednoc fo stelpord llams desuac
.yllaer toN“  "?si eh erehw wonk uoY“
.yawllah niam eht ni pu enola eb ot tnaw
uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
,htiw gnola teg ot ysae saw eh ,sesod llams nI
".tnaw uoy fi ni emoC .surriS ,haeY“
,krad erew saera oidrac dna thgiew ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tnereffid yna eb dluow sgniht detbuod eH
.anuas eht ot denepo taht rood ssalg detsorf eht dna srekcol fo noitces elgnis a evoba morf emac
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
edam d'ehs ekac noffihc yrrebwarts dekab emoh a thguorb daetsni dah dna
erew eugnot knip fo sehcni elpuoc a dna ,detrap saw elzzum sih ,surriS dedrager eh sa neve dna ,gnitaews ylraelc saw flow
.erus ,ti kcuf tuB“
.krow retfa eivom a ot em ekat ot detnaw eH
,god.ecioveht ta
".tnaw uoy fi mih gnigap yrt dluoc I
.kcapkcab sih gnitsujda niaga
.gnimoc ti sah enoemos sselnu etib t'nod I ,draeh evah yam uoy tahw etipseD“
.ytiniffAruF dna yrruFoS
.neht ecnis krow ta yad tsrif sih neeb dah siht tub
,ria eht ni erutsiom eht morf nwod dekcils ruf sih htiW .loohcs hgih ni dah eh ekil tuo dekrow llits eh
,eloC ,raey namhserf 'surriS gnirud tub ,egelloc ytinummoc gnidnetta yltnerruc saw yug ehT
.rehtom sih fo ycrem eht ta saw eh
,esuap a saw erehT  ".sseug I
.niaga ekops flow eht ,revewoh ,rood eht no wap sih tup eh sA
stnemmoc ssatrams htiw elbuort pu rits ot ycnednet a dah llits eh tub
,noitseggus 'surriS yb
,htaerb peed a koot eH
drawrof rewop eht saw maS
".dab ytterp nettog s'mrots ehT
.no srexob sih peek ot detpmet saw eh
.rebmemer dluoc eh sa gnol sa
.mrots eht otni tuo dehsur neht
.rood eht ot kcab gnikool erofeb erom ecno gnitfihs ,daeh sih fo don evitamriffa na evag surriS
mih dehsubma dah srekrowoc sih ,yllarutan ,oS
.thguoht fo sdnoces wef a retfa pu evig ot demees ehs tub ,rettam eht hsup ot gniog saw ehs ekil demees ahsirT
.flesmih ot tpek yltsom flow eht
saw ffats eht suolucitem woh wenk eh os
,elbissop sa hcum sa meht dediova eH
,reh ot derrucco aedi na sa ,revewoH
".nuf ekil sdnuos tahT“
,laturb neeb dah ecitcarp
".emoh uoy teg ylbaborp nac eH
".pu hsinif nac uoy ,ereh enod ton
".ereht tuo dednarts gnitteg uoy evah t'naC
,moor maets eht fo edis eno ta gnivom erugif derrulb a ees did eh ,smrof tcnitsid yna ees t'ndluoc eh hguohtlA
.daeh sih koohs eH
.yad yraerd a hcus no retsum dluoc god a ylno taht eciov yreehc fo dnik eht ni
,tnemom a rof srood tnorf s'bulc citelhta eht tuo dekool neht
.maet 'surriS no
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
peels neht dna ,deb otni lwarc
,pihsnoitaler rieht tuoba aedi gnorw eht tog eh fi yug eht emalb t'ndluow eH
.edistuo krad dna dloc saw ti nehw neve
.dluoc ehs revenehw sruoh artxe ekat ot reh dedeen yeht hcum woh wenk eh – reh tsniaga krow ot reh rof deen eht dloh t'ndid eH
,tib a detfihs eH
,moor rekcol eht otni deppets eh nehW
wenk surriS tub ,eromyna llabteksab yalp t'ndid eloC
.elballys tsrif eht no gnikcarc eciov sih ,tuo detrulb surriS
",yaw ym no yllaer ton s'tI“ .kcen
smaet eht ot noitnetta gniyap saw dworc eht taht gniveileb otni flesmih klat dluoc eh esuaceb llabteksab eldnah dluoc eH
,ni emoc yltsom dah ruf retniw foorpretaw siH  .sruoh rof
,rood eht denepo eh sA
t'ndid eH .noitativni eht rof lufknaht saw eh tub ,looc ti yalp ot deirt
.sromur ydaerla erew ereht tub ,epyt suolaej eht yltcaxe t'nsaw maS .surriS
.mih dniheb hcneb detavele eht no swoble sih detser neht
,etoyoc emos htiw thgif a otni nettog d'eh ,yltnerappA
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.hteet emos tsol dah rettal eht dna
deifitrom tlef d'eh tluser a sA
.deggurhs neht ,desuap eh
.sekalf kciht ni nwod gnilriws wons fo snmuloc niwt detanimulli sthgildaeh thgirb ehT
.yrgna tlef llits eh
.gnihtyreve htiw dehsinif er'uoy nehw edir a em evig dluoc uoy fi gnirednow tsuj saw I“
.ssecorp ot mih rof redrah elttil a saw
.eson sih debbur ylevixelfer eh ,mih dniheb desolc rood eht sA
.yltcerid mih naht rehtar
.ti htrow ecneirepxe elohw eht edam tsomla dah gnippot maerc dna yrrebwarts ehT
ytrap "esirprus“ dekab-flah a htiw
".yrruh a ni s'maS ekil sdnuoS
.eussi tuohtiw setammaet sih htiw smoor rekcol dna srewohs eht ni emit fo ytnelp tneps d'eH
noitanimulli rehto ylno eht moor rekcol eht dessorc eh sa ,gnithgil ytiruces sediseB
,rood til ylthgirb eht sdrawot deppets eH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ssa na fo tib a saw eh tub ,htiw krow ot yug hguone KO na saw eloC
.seye s'flow eht ni deraeppa ytisoiruc fo kraps a dna
ro noitcart erit ekil sgniht htiw dia ot hcum od t'ndluow tahT
.eloC dnif ot setunim net tuoba mih koot tI
detaes saw ,flow derruf-kcalb eht