”.tnaw uoy fi uoy rof tuo ti lleps nac I .won thgir yob evarb a hcus gnieb er’uoY“
,delkcuhc raeb eht
”.tnellecxe si bus A“
”.retal smaerd rieht ni eb annog er’eW
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.dniheb morf mih dleh eh sa ygolopa ni keehc dna kcen s’flow eht revo gnissik ,dias raeb eht ”.ssatrams
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
swap deot etihw dna shgiht erab siH
,gaw tub pleh t’ndluoc ayaW
,kcab sih revo eralg deyonna na raeb eht gnitoohs
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”!uoy fo duorp os m’I
gnittuc naom gnirepmihw prahs A
.kcab sih tsniaga pu desserp eh sa hgih liat taht gnitfil dna gnipsarg wap mrif ecnO
.mih tog tahw s’tahT
...nobbir ecalp tsrif a evah dluohs uoY“
sih ni denetsaf srehtaef yekrut eht ot dehcatta t’nsaw tI
ees uoy did ,sediseB .taht naht retteb gnihtoN .uoy htiw m’I“
,yb mih gnissap dworc gniltsub eht fo tuo dna
”.spu-kooh tsrow net pot eht no ylisaE
”.nisuoc s’erah taht wonk I erus ytterp m’I
.eerf flesmih llup ot ,gniliaf dna tseb sih gniyrt ,dekrab flow eht
edis eht ot ffo htolc taht fo edisrednu eht hsup ot hguone tsuj
erofeb deye-ediw dna kcurtsewa
.liat sih htiw deyalp eh sa ecalp ni mih gnidloh raeb eht
.erac t’ndid eh dna ruf s’mra sih otno tib a ffo emoc esaerg eht leef dluoc eH
siht ekil flesruoy yrrac llits nac uoy
,evaw a ekil gniltsirb kcab sih nopu ruF
.rehtegot kcip ot dekil yeht seirrebwarts eht sa der sa srae
,tsiaw s’dneirfyob sih dnuora sttim raeb gib esoht fo eno dils anoY ”.tib a noitisoper s’teL
”.em htiw lla fo tsaeL .yppah eb ot thgir eht nrae ot evah t’nod uoY“
.mih dniheb sruof lla no flesmih denoitisop dneirfyob a fo niatnuom sih sa gnikaeuqs rac eht
.liat sih rednu sepahs werd eh sa htrof dna kcab dils dooh sih yaw eht tlef eH
.sdneirfyob esrow s’mom sih fo eno morf worbeye etisoppo sih no tuc A .efil reh gnivas
daeherof eht dniheb ni gnittes tnemssarrabme deretsulf eht gnidih ,dias
,hsalc duol a htiw drawrof gnispalloc
.edis s’ayaW otni gnisserp
”.amdnarg ruoy pu-taeb dluoc amdnarg yM .dluohs ehS“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sdap wap sih fo sevruc eht revo ecart eugnot taht tlef eH
.revelc sa debircsed syawla anoY seye wolley siH
.gnos eht ni ecalp ruoy dna spets ruoy rebmemer ot uoy tuoba dnim ruoy peek tub
.evil ot woh togrof I gnol os rof evivrus ot gniyrt neeb ev’I .doG“
”-eg ot gniyrt eb d’I
kcab eht ni but a evah dluohs I“
.htob meht llik annog m’I hO“.rehtegot
raeb eht ”?ayaW idsU em rof ffilc a no ciots lla esop annog uoY“
,evig ot erom dah eh ,enod saw eh thguoht raeb eht emit yrevE
inohaS“ raG yb ”’nigganS“
.kcab sih no thgiew eht fo hsurc rednet a fo gnileef eht ot
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
srae enipul llat ni
.shtaerb neewteb noitatirri ni eugnot sih dekcilc eH
.rac eht ni kcab sehtolc fo egnahc a tog I dnA .socat
sdrow eht neewteb tnemesumeb gnikrims ,syas yob flow eht
.detnaw uoy gniht taht yrt dluoc I ,sediseB“
dna ti denrae t’nevah I ekil leef I .lla ti fo tib
raf os emac uoY“ .yltneg dias raeb ehT
.nwo sih sa flow eht gnirovas dna gnilriws ,eloh
?em gniddik uoy erA“  ”.retteb nwonk evah dluohs I“
.deffuh eh sa gnikcilf rae detniop eno ,denraw flow eht ”.uoy
.si mih naht regnuoy enoyreve skniht eh ,yllanosrep ti ekat t’nod tuB
,mih htiw kcab eht otni debmilc eh sa
.pu flesmih enil ot nwod dehcaer eh sa gninnirg
ecnatsid eht ni ffo erehwemoS
.eb nac uoy wonk I
slanoitpecxE  fo rengised emag dna retirw a ,sniktA
dna nisuoc sih ffo poc suoicipsus a gnithgif morf rae thgir sih ni hcton ehT
.liat sih fo esab eht yb ecalp ni mih dleh dneirfyob eh sa tuo gnilbmert seenk
daerbyrf su tog I os taht retfa tae ot gnihtemos tnaw dluow uoy derugif I“
.dab mih detnaw raeb ehT
”.egaw muminim erom oN“
.ynoP raW eht tsniaga mih hsup ot thgiew sih gnisu
”.roirraw lufrewop dna evarb a hcus htiw emit emos dneps ot tnaw I !esaelP .nom’C“ .kcab rewol s’dneirfyob sih tsniaga dorp niatrec ylevissergga na dna sdrow sih ni yenoh htiw gnidaelp ,dias raeb eht ”.gnihtyreve
,delkcuhc sraeb eht ”.ecreif oS“
”.kcoc ym ekat ot edam tsuj si uoy ekil yppup ytterP“
htgnel krad kciht
gib uoy neht rewol kciL“
.shgiht citelhta esoht neewteb esool gniws sllab derruf etihw yvaeh esoht dehctaw eh sa naorg tub pleh t’ndluoc raeb kcalb gib ehT
,detneler flow eht
,pu tel t’ndid anoY ,ti dnuof eh ecnO
.era sklof dlo eht erehw koobecaf no syawla si ohw lrig naem atsni gib taht si yug rehto eht dna
,eugnot eninac ediw s’dneirfyob sih htiw deyot eH
.htaerb peed a koot flow eht
”!roirraw elttil etirovaf ym s’erehT
rewol dneirfyob sih gnihsup
”?tahw esaelP“  ”...esaelP“
htaerb gnitnap dna sesruc tneliS
.mom kcis sih fo erac ekat ot emoh gninruter dna edirp sih wollaws ot gnivah erofeB
”?ti od yllanif annog uoY ?haeY !ohO“
.erac htiw deilppa sgnaf prahs dna
,dedeen raeb eht noissimrep eht lla saw tahT
.mlap s’dneirfyob sih tsniaga bmuht sih debbur eH
.dekcuf yeht sa meht ta gnireel
.edirp sih dna flesmih rof
,elbmert flow eht ekam ot hguone saw tI
”.ezeeuqs uoy leef ot tnaw I“
,srae s’dneirfyob sih neewteb daeh sih detser eh sa htrof dna kcab gniyaws ,eciov gnos-gnis a ni gnas anoY ”.ton er’uoy oN“   .lworg ciots a ta tpmetta na htiw edam eh repmihw gnissarrabme eht pu gnirevoc
srebmun ognib tuo dellac
.taebtraeh a si murd eht ,wow-wop a ta ecnad uoy nehW
.ezeerb eht ni gnippalf snobbir eeb wolley yenoh dna etihW .trihs nobbir denrettap wolley dna kcalb sih fo mottob eht pu gnitfil
,mih nioj dna kcab yal saw od dluoc
”.em ta gniralg syawla s’eH“
,seye eltneg esoht morf yawa dekool eh sa gnikcilf rae eno ,tuo delworg flow eht ”.pots
,shtaerb gnitnap neewteb tuo dekrab flow eht
.tib a rof kcab eht ni tuo gnah nac eW“
,sessik neewteb dias raeb eht
emit yreve tub nwod dekconk teg uoY
erofeb troffe elttil htiw mra eno rednu mih gnitfil
ti sa reve naht reffits kcoc siH
yb uoy rof daer
.sselemoh gnieb erofeB
sniktA ”inohaS“ raG yb ” ’nigganS“
,deilper raeb eht
!’niggans m’I tsael
ot pit morf pu eugnot sih gniggard
flow eht ”.tsrif emoh tub ,haeY“
,dniheb morf sllab gnignah-wol sih gnipolevne
.elpuoc eht rof dereehc yeht sa snip ytefas dna ,snottub cinori ,sehtolc yggab llA
,llat gnidnats ,dias raeb eht
.pets peek ot tluciffid ti gnikam murd eht htiw dednelb dna
.pirg nori sih nesool ot mih teg ot hgiht s’ayaW gnittap
,sredluohs daorb sih ffo esool gnuh taht ebor eht rednU
.elzzum sih ni gnitsurht sregnif eht yb delffum lworg flow dab gib tseb sih ,dias flow eht
.redluohs sih revo eralg livederad a dna
.ssik eht otni denael eh sa gnilgnij sgnirrae dedaeb
rethgit hcnelc mih gnileef
.rohpatem tnatum eht ecneirepxe ew hcihw hguorht sesnel eht dna
htmraw tew A .hgiht renni sih pu delevart eugnot eht sa gnimriuqs spih
dah eH .htob meht rof hguor neeb dah raey tsap siht wenk eH
.kcab s’flow eht no gnitser ylleb
”.yawa tup dna ffo sehtolc eseht teg ot deen eW“
.shgiht knurt eert sih no gnitser kcoc gninetfos
,nibac tnorf eht otni erats ylno dluoc eH
.tleb sih htaenrednu wap a edils ot yrt raeb eht tlef eh sa gnimriuqs spih
,htaerb sih no sucof sih dna teef sih rednu ssarg yrd fo hcnurc eht saw ydob sih ot derehtet mih gnipeek gniht ylno ehT
,dehsif raeb eht ”?...em
.dworc eht ni raeppasid ot yawa mih deggut rehtom sih
.esion hcum oot gnikam morf peek ot deirt eh sa htaerb sih rednu gnilworg ,hteet sih tirg eH .htgnel lluf sti ot
mih dniheb dah flow eht naht thgiew erom tol a htiw kcab gninael ,syas raeb eht ”.em
,did uoy fi neve dnA“
.siht ekil regnol hcum tsal ot gniog t’nsaw eH
.tlih eht ot yawflah htrae yalc der eht fo efink sih naelc ot erac taerg gnikat ,dias flow ehT
.daeh sih evoba meht gninnip dna tsirw s’flow eht htob gnibbarg
”?wonk uoy rehcaet taerg a ekam ot gniog er’uoY
.taeh detnecs renehserf rac yrrehc ykcits eht ni dekaos yeht sa
.mih rednu dexelf kcoc sih sa gnilruc seot
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.siht rof gnitiaw neeb ev’I“
,deggaw flow ehT  ”.lliw syawla I dnA“
,flesmih ta dekool eh nehw tuB
,kcab gnirats tsiruot dik taog emos was eh sa
,mih desirprus eh nehw dekcilf srae dednuor s’dneirfyob sih yaw eht dekil ayaW
,esool gniws ot gninetaerht sgnirrae walc raeb dna llehs
don dna elims llams a gnivig
.txen ssik dna kcil ot erehw ediced dna yrt eugnot eht tlef eh sa
.deralf slirtson sih sa tsrif ta rorrim eht tub erehwyreve gniteem seye
.tnaw uoy tahw wonk uoY“
,ailager sih ot dennip
,ylleb sih tsniaga gnitser kcoc tucnu nworb siH
.esolc mih gnidloh
eht htiw dna niatnuom eht sa daorB
tuop a ni flesmih ot deffuh eH .psag
.rorrim weiv raer eht ni thguac eh tahw morf ot pu saw raeb eht yltcaxe tahw tuo elzzup ot gniyrt
,spih s’dneirfyob rellams sih gnippirg swap gib
dluoc yeht sa hcum sa kcab gnidlof srae
.hguorht gninnur doohdlihc a tneps eh sdoow eht fo mih dednimer taht sder dna snworb htiw degnit ,ruf etihw dna yerg htiw flow rebmit a ,hguone railimaf saw tI
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER
,noitceffa htiw peed delworg flow eht ”.fooD
”.taht naht retteb od nac uoY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.laog sih dna mih neewteb doots taht lla erew sdnoces 03 dna
,raeb eht fo edis rehtie no detser
.rac a fo nietsneknarF tuo-detsur sih fo pot no
” .yawa ti fo tnemom a edart t’ndluow I
.yrreb remmus a ekil ayaW detsat eugnot taht sa skeehc esoht gnizarg sgnaF
.sgnaf sih dniheb gnikcilc eugnot
.rac fo tol a ton dna raeb fo tol a si erehT“
.dleif taht no tuo dah eh tahw naht etavirp erom elttil a gnihtemos ot decnad eugnot rieht sa keehc sih otni gnigdun gnir eson
.meht tih ria dloc taht sa
.tniap esaerg kcalb dna der eht dna sgnirrae dewalc sih htaenrednU
.retsasid etulosba na saw sihT“
.stiucsib yob nrehtuos
,delbmum flow eht ”.uoy evol I“
yojne esaelP  .ytiniffaruF ro
erofeb seye sih dellor dna eugnot sih dekcilc flow ehT
pin yttarb a rof gnilttes flow ehT
.edis rieht otno htob meht tfihs ot tnemevom gnitfihs elpmis a saw tI
si yrots s’yadoT dna
esohT ”.og uoy erehT“ .mhtyhr ydaets
erofeb elims yls a htiw pu dekool flow retrohs eht
.gnirevoc taes htolc eht otni gniggid swalc kcalb llud siH
.noitom wols ni dlrow eht ekil tlef ti
elpoep owt fo swodahs eht gnihctac seye ,deppots eH
,og ot esle erehwon htiw tfel neeb dah flow ehT
smraerof sih dniheb ecaf sih gnidiH
.srae sih fo spit eht ot delevart hsulb gninrub eht sa hcum os od ylno dluoc
.pots ot nehw uoy llet ll’I“
.smaes eht yb trapa rac eht ekahs ot gninetaerht saw ti ekil tlef spih sih fo egnulp gnikcub hcaE
ydob sih tsniaga htaerb toH
,erah a dna mussop a ,starb gnihtemosneet owt fo secaf dehsums eht ,rac eht edistuo
.ni gnittes yllanif noitsuahxe ,denaorg flow eht
.em edisni uoy tnaw I ,esaelP“  .raeb eht ta eugnot sih dekcilc eh sa gnikcilf rae eno ,delworg flow eht ”.em edisni uoy tnaw I ,esaelP“
.keehc s’ayaW revo dessik eh sa deksa raeb eht
”.won rof bus a ylno m’I“
.noitcerid rehto eht ni kcen sih gnillup kcen sih dnuora ettegrog revlis
redrah elttil a spih sih gnikcor
.eno naht syaw erom ni ayaW gniddorp yltneg
.eciov yls tseb sih ni dias anoY
,thgit yromem eht dleh eH
.esool edils ot deirt eh sa dneirfyob sih gninoitisoper
sehcuot retfos htiw rehto hcae gnisserdnu sdnah esraoc fo hctip revef A
.tsehc sih ot pu gnimoc ylno ayaW
tcaf eht dna hcum os hguorht thguof ev’uoY
”.reloohcs edarg a erew uoy ekil sdaeb fo lluf sdnah htiw reh ot txen gnittis uoy rebmemer I dnA .rebmemer I“  ”.shtnom
,pu werd sllab eh sa citarre werg gnitsurht siH
.oot kcab mih esaet ot woh tsuj wenk raeb ehT
.rorrim rac eht sdrawot mih gnitniop dna sredluohs sih yb flow eht gnippirg ylmrif
,liat sih rednu gniffuh raeb ehT
.trapa gnillaf sa tuoba tsuj saw tI
.retsaf hcum taht lla swodniw eht gniggof
,dworc eht gnoma tops ot ysae nam raeb kcalb
”.tsael ta gab reelodnab dna tekcaj eht ffo ekat em tel attog uoy tuB !enif yakO“
.deniur saw tnemom eht tub
.gnilggiw ydaerla liat ,sksa raeb eht
.lwocs sih netfos tub pleh t’ndluoc eh ,dekool yllaer
”.rorrim eht ni kool ot uoy tnaw I“
.eciov sih ni gnilggiw liat sdneirfyob sih raeh yllacitcarp dluoc ayaW
”.taht ekil thgim eh kniht I .haey tuB...nobbir
,tsurht yreve otni kcab flow eht dellup raeb tesyvaeh ehT
”.nehctik eht ni gnihtemos rof gnihcaer pleh ym deen uoy emit txen taht rebmemer ll’I ,mhM“  ”.sufood
,yaw eht ni tog htolc eht nehW
,thgieh lluf sih ot pu gnidnats erofeb yltfos syas raeb eht
denimreted a wohs dna decaf yeht lla ni ecnad siht tpek taht srotsecna eht ronoh ot woh dnif ot evah uoy ,recnad doog a eb oT
.tnemom siht kaerb thgim ti deracs saw eh fi sa
”.pu nettog kcab ev’uoy
tA“ delley flow eht tub derettacs yeht sa kcab edurc gnihtemos detuohs sneet ehT
”?doog did I kniht yllaer uoy oD ?anoY yeH“
dah eH .kcehcyap txen sih htiw pu emos kcip dluoc eh
daeh sih revo hgih dleh eh setalp repap gib eht eb reisae edam ,eb dluoc sraeb ylno yaw eht ni llat
.tcapmi rof decarb eH
,ycnegru dewener a htiw sih tsniaga pu gnidnirg koot rekciht retrohs s’raeb eht
.efil htiw dehsulf ylippah
”.deen I gnihtyreve htiw
.dedne loohcs hgih erofeb ebyaM
.hgual rettib a htiw syas flow eht
,gnirettacs owt eht dnes ot hguone saw ti ,saw ti sa evitceffenI
.taes kcab eht tsniaga
,tnuat dna toh meht daerps eh sa spil sih dekcil raeb ehT
”.emoh gniklaw er’uoy ro rorrim eht ta gnikool er’uoY“
,deffuh flow eht ”rehgih elttil A“
”?rebmemer roirraw a er’uoY .ti rof ksA
.doolf a ekil htrof dellips dna dloh ot hcum oot saw ti litnu
,delbmur raeb eht ”.ksa si
”.tnellecxe si drihT“
”.siht no sniats yna tog I fi em llik dluow amdnarG ym dna
.shtnom rof trihs siht gnikam saw ehS
.yltneg degru raeb eht
.seidob revo dils sdnah sa tsaf sa tsomla yggof tog tekcor zer ytsur rieht fo swodniw ehT
,seldnah ekil srae dednuor esoht deppirg eH  .ezag sih peek ot yhs oot
.ssenevisnefed lautibah ni tsehc sih fo tnorf ni gnissorc smra sih
srae enipul esoht otni delworg raeb eht
taht nialpxe ot tnaw t’nod yllaer I dnA“
.tsrif emoh teg s’teL“
”.gniht elohw eht ekat ,thgir s’tahT“
.mih htiw nwod edils eugnot gnol taht gnittel dna
.lanimirc a sa mih detaert taht ssob a rednu urht-
ayaW llA  ”.uoy saw taht nehw rebmemer I“
.tnereffid tlef ti tuoba gnihtemos tuB
”...dab gib no dloH“  .kcab sih dehcra eh sa slirtson sih gniralf ffuh gnol A
”.mih rof slian eht dloh em ekam ot esu dad ym nehw ekil dekool uoY“
ecno ta lla uoy edisni ti fo lla niatnoc ot evah uoY
”.dnim ruoy egnahc reve uoy fi wonk uoY“
.edis s’raeb yvaeh daorb eht tsniaga spmuht flah gnikam liat yggahs nwo sih
.yppah flesmih was dna rorrim eht ni dekool eh emit tsal eht rebmemer t’ndluoc eH
.htaerb flesmih tlef eh dna ,sucof ni dlrow eht tup ot hguone saw anoY  .ylleb kcalb yzzuf tfos taht fo keep eht ta hsulf flesmih tlef ayaW
.roirraw a er’uoY“
,kcab rewol s’dneirfyob sih pu swap sih gnidils
.kcen sih nwod edils dneirfyob sih tlef eh sa esion eht hguorht
htaerb sih rednu sloot sih fo hcae ot uoy knaht delbmum eH
.rethgual detaorht lluf otni gniworg elkcac ,dias flow eht
”?emosdnah trihs-t noitats sag ro nav detniap ekiL ?haeY“
,dias raeb eht ”...em dna uoy tsuJ
,sdnoces erom 03 tsal saw od ot dah ti llA
,srieht saw ti tuB
d’taht ,eerf emac meht fo yna fI
mih fo edisni raj a ekil truh tsehc siH
”?floW evarB .rM enob ruoy htiw uoy pleh ot em tnaw uoy oD“
.htolc-hceerb sih fo mirb eht gnicart swalc
sadacic remmus eht fo sgnos tsal eht morf
.meht rof tsuj trap tsal eht gnirepsihw ,syas anoY ”ayaW idsU duorp eb ot teg I .erac t’nod I“
.hcum tib a eb ot gnitteg saw tI
.erom ecno raeb eht otni gninael
.sufood em naht rellat hcum taht t’nia uoy dnA“
yffulf s’flow sih fo
flesruoy ta kool ot uoy tnaw I“
”.oot uoy evol I dnA .wonk I“
.liat s’ayaW fo ssem a gnikam dna tuo gnipees dees
,deralg ayaW ”.eniF“
,traeh ruoy lla htiw tnemevom hcae leef ot evah uoY
,dias raeb eht ”.t’now uoy oN“
derahs yeht sgniht eht morf yawa emit dna yenom ehT
”.trapa llaf ot lla ti rof gnitiaw ma tsuj I
yrgnuh m’I ,nom’C“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
nobbir ehT .eulb eht dekil eH
dneirfyob sih ,anoY
ot evah ot ydaer tsuj m’I
”.amdnarG ym ot niats ralucitrap
.skeehc sih neewteb dnirg raeb eht leef dluoc eH
.doof ruo elots yeht kniht I dna yrgnuh os m’I“ gnihgual llits
kcab s’flow eht revo ti deppilf anoY
,tleb htolc eht gninesool detrats eh erofeb taes kcab eht ni eb ot ayaW rof detiaw ylerab anoY
.htuom sih tfel ti erofeb derewsna noitseuq sih dnuof flow eht ”-reht
.ecalp taht tcetorp ot gnihtyna od d’eH
”.ecaf ym hsaw annaw I
evird eht ta stfihs gniniard-lliw eht erofeB
,kcab delworg raeb eht
.yalpsid no soottat lanoitidart sih fo sdnab roirraw eht gnittup
.tuo lla ti hgual ot deirt eh sa ykahs llits htaerb ,dias flow eht
,ria eht ni hgih liat dna tsrif tsiaw saw eh ti wenk ayaW erofeB
yas ot enoemos rof gnitiaw tsuj m’I .thgif
.edisrednu derruf etihw sih tsniaga deloord ti sa desopxe ylerab daeh knip teews
dnuora er’uoy nehw tub ,gnorts taht eb reve dluoc I fi wonk t’nod I
!eyA“  ...gnihtyreve retfa laicos gnieb ot esu t’nsaw llits eH
efas tlef syawla eh
”.siht lla ni emosdnah ytterp kool od uoY“
,lworg yhtaerb rehtona htiw derettum flow eht
etalp repap dekaos esaerg eht gnicalp ,dias raeb eht
”.od I ekil uoy wonk t’nseod eh dnA
.tol gnikrap eht hguorht delbmuts yeht sa
yllanif erofeb meht htaenrednu dekaerc dna delttar kcab taes ehT
mih gniworht
.rewolf a no wed ekil taews eht gnirehtag eugnot
,dehcnuh tpek eh sa dnah eno ni ylmrif dehctulc bulcraw a ,retsaf nups ayaW
”.dnoces a rof flesruoy ta kool tsuJ .rorrim eht ni
eciov sih ni elggiw liat eht raeh yllacitcarp dluoc ayaW
”...tuoba yrrow ot evah t’nod ew erehW .ecalp ruo fo ytefas eht nI
.segduj eht htiw stniop mih tsoc
.sroloc otni derrulb srehcaelb eht ni seilimaf eht sa sucof tsol seye siH
,delworg raeb eht ”.ton er’uoy oN“
,flow eht debbarg raeb eht ”.ereh emoC !yeH“
.roirraw a er’uoy rebmemer dnA
,mih dniheb llat doots anoY
daeh s’flow eht fo pot eht gnissik
”...tluaf ym saw siht ,nuh yrros m’I“
.resol gib a er’uoy skniht eh esuaceb s’tahT“
,degdun raeb eht  ”...ecin
nobbir eht ta nwod dekool eH
,rulb a ni mih dniheb gnipeews liat yggahs dna gniralf slirtson flow tew
.pu flow eht elir d’ti gniwonk ,dias anoY
siht otni flesmih fo hcum os tup
.erac lufroloc htiw detfarc lla erew taht bulc raw dna ,efink dna ,lehctas sih rO .riah
”!selohssa uoy tnemesab samdnarg ruoy ni ffo krej oG
.erom ecno erusopmoc sih dnif ot deirt eh sa sccom sih ni gnixelf seot siH
dna rehgih ti gnicrof
.noitisop siht ni elbarenluv os tlef eH
,sniktA ”inohaS“ raG yb
”nigganS“ saw sihT     ”.doof
”.nobbir ecalp driht a evah I .resol a ton m’I“
.sdrac hsalf ruoy dloh em edam uoy esuaceb ecno ta htob gniod uoy was I .tset ruoy lla rof gniyduts uoy was I
.wodniw eht ta skcals s’anoY worht ot gnilbmarcs yletarepsed waP
.retneprac decitcarp a ekil nwod gniremmah ,ecap pu dekcip eh sa ti otni denael anoY
staeb eht htiw gniyalp si pmots dna tnemevom hcaE
.daeherof sih revo daerps esaerg dna hsa eht revo driew tlef taews ehT
nosdnarg s’redle taht si ecaf-sih-s’tahw taht wonk uoY ,sediseB“
pit sti morf erp fo enil toh raelc a tfel
.ecin tlef ti tub ,ecalp driht saw
”.trap siht ta doog yrev neeb reven ev’I“
.ssik a otni desserp eh erofeb lworg lufyalp a mih gnivig
.htaerb gniredduhs a ni gnilahxE
.kcab wap sih gnizeeuqs
,ylduorp deffuh ayaW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,edis s’dneirfyob sih tsniaga dna
.htrig eht ot detsujda eh sa sraeb eht htiw gniknil sregnif
.railimaf gnihtemos rof dworc eht revo tuo dekool eH
.od ot tahw dlot gnieb ta esnopser lautcnitsni na
tnorferots sih no seirots lanoisacco dna sesaeler emag wen tuoba nrael nac uoY
,roirraw a dellac gnieb ta ffo gnitteg saw mih fo trap emos yned t’ndluoc eh dnA
dednuop traeh siH
.era uoy gnorts woh swohs
kcab gniod uoy era tahw
.mrof regral sih htaeneb ayaW dehsurc anoY sa gnikaerc sgnirps
,feiler ni dehgis eh anoY ta pu dekool ayaW sA
seracs amdnarG ruoY“
.peed gnihtemos tsniaga dnuorg raeb eht sa
,saw raeb eht gums woh tsuj was eh nehw
”.traeh ruoy lla htiw decnad uoY
,esolc delzzun raeb eht
.liob a ot anoY thguorb wenk eh ekil sbmuht sih htiw selppin nworb sih revo gnicart sregnif ,scep sih revo dezeeuqs swalc siH
eno siht piks esaelp
”.ayaW idsU ksa si od ot evah uoy llA“
.eugnot taht otni kcab hsup tub pleh t’ndluoc eh gnituop sih etipseD
.won thgir emoh ton er’ew ykcul os er’uoY“
htgnel sih gniggut wap esool a
.tneve siht rof decitcarp uoy gnol woh nees ev’I
.suoivbo saw ti sselnU
.flow eht sserdnu ot gnol ekat t’ndid tI
”.ees I ohw ees ot uoy tnaw I“
.kcab ot ylleb ,thgit mih dleh dna
kniht I .raeppasid lla ti ekam dna ti yas ot enoemos rof tsuj m’I ekil leef I
.uoy etib ot gniog m’I“
.tnaem taht tahw nrael ot fo duorp saw eh naht regnol hcum os mih koot ti dna
.eciov yrw a ni dias flow eht
”.taht sees eh litnu tiaW“
.raeb fo elzzum eht ni mrif eno htiw
seveels denetsaf telecarb sti
.flow sih ni peed debborht dna dehctiwt eh sa gnidnirg raeb teews ,deppots neht
,detseggus nisuoc sih ekil daerht yretslohpu eht desu evah dluohs eH
.thgiew eht rednu gnikcor rac
”!svrep uoy ffo kcuF !yE“
nirg a hguorht desaet flow eht
”.duorp os eb d’ehs wonk uoy ees dluoc mom ruoy fi wonk tsuj I .raey a tsuj ni
.liat sih no slleb eht evomer ayaW gnipleh ,deksa
”.em seracs dad ruoY“
dna tsenrae na htiw tops taht gnittih
dna denimreted dna lufrewop dekool eH .duorp dekool eH
.nodnaba etanoissap ni htgnel lluf sih gnimmar
,semaG floW elbmarB yb
”.boj wen ruoy no yllaicepsE
,rac eht ni kcab despalloc flow ehT
.htolc ni seceip reggib eht pu gnipparw
.nrut ni ti nruter dworc eht evah ot ylno ,tuo deirc eh sa gnilgnij slleb reppoc
ot tnaem eh naht ecrof erom tib a htiw dneirfyob sih gnipmub pih ,dias raeb eht
.derettahs neeb dah ecalp ni sgnileef eseht lla gnidloh
”.uoy ekam I duorp woh em wohS .foog
”.yadnoM krow rof ti deen I .ynoP raW eht kaerb t’noD“ tuo dehgual ayaW ”...llab gnikcerW“
,eenk s’flow eht rednu mra na dekooh raeb eht sa hsurb yvaeh tniap a ekil erp gnikcilf dna gnicnuob kcoc s’ayaW .tsurht hcae htiw elgnij gnirrae s’eninac eht gnikam ,flow eht gnicnuob tsurht rellams ,delworg eh
”htaerb ym hctac ot gniyrt neeb tsuj ev’I ,haeY“
,rewoterif a ekil llat doots
”...doog eno uoy kcos annog m’I“   .repeed gud dna
.eivom dlo eno taht morf ekil ynop raw sih ti dellac yehT
.resolc elttil a dneirfyob sih dellup raeb eht
.knip yzoc a ot dehsulf ,sdrow sih lla gnilbmum-flah ,syas flow eht
ydob sih ot nruter flesmih tlef eh emit eht yB
,sevlesruo rof dliub sklof dezilanigram taht secaps eht rof dna tuoba ,nem-x yb deripsni emag a
.troppus tnelis ni kcab sih no liat sih tser ayaW evah ot ylno ,hgis deggar nwo sih htiw syas raeb eht
od ot evah uoy llA“
”.wonk uoy driht tog ylno I“
tfos rehtona pu revoc ot gnilworg
eno denrae t’nevah I
,staes eht pirg dna hcnilf mih gnikam
,tiaW“  ”.doog tae annog m’I
.hteet sih neewteb srae esoht fo eno koot eh sa
.dnah sih ni ylthgit dehctulc llits drac
,reniatnoc erawrepput a ni yrlewej sih decalp ylluferac dna tibah fo tuo
.yawa lla ti tup ot locotorp eht rebmemer ot deirt eh sa ecneirepxe tnereffid yrev a saw tluda na sa tub ,dik a sa ecnad ot esu eH
ecalp a saw anoY .seye tseltneg
noitapicitna suovren ni hctiwt ti hctaw ot tnemom a gnikat
.drawrof gnivom uoy fo ecaf gninihs
,hteet sih tsniaga eugnot sih gnikcilc ,dekool flow ehT
yltcerid gnikool er’yeht sselnu su ees ot gniog si eno oN“
.foor eht gniparcs dna ffits dleh liat
.nwo sih tsniaga niks mraw
.ecin eB“  .elbarenluv eb ot drah saw ti dnA
.egde s’ti no gniliob ,ylleb sih revo dehcuotnu dna denodnaba ,dehctiwt kcoc nwo siH
ayaW rof reisae elttil a ti edam eh sa
.niaga etad tsrif rieht tuoba kniht ot tog yeht ynop raw a ti dellac yeht emityreve dna
.eton no tih uoy sa roloc lanretni fo noisolpxe citenik eht dna sgnis redael eht sa seton neewteb gnivaeW
,dezigolopa anoY
”...sseug I doog ytterp si drihT“
.noitcirf dna thgiew eht morf htrof dna kcab gnillor nikserof
.rorrim siht ni flesruoy rebmemer ot uoy tnaw I .ecalp krad taht ni er’uoy emit txeN“
.mhtyhr eht ot cnys uoy sa
.mih dniheb tuo dellac eciov gnimoob tub railimaf a
”taht od ew fi su ees lliw enoemoS“
.shgiht renni dna smra sih revo soottat sih decart sdnah s’raeb eht sa
.elzzum sih fo edis rehtie no mraw worg spit detniop esoht leef dluoc eH
,ylduorp dekrab flow eht ”!ti hsup t’noD“
rekaeps nekorb a
”?ti tnaw uoy od wol woH“
.ecaps eht dellif taht gninaom delffum eht gninioj
ecap ydaets wols a ni ayaW otni gnisae
.tniap ecaf eht edisgnola ecalp ni llits sgnirrae reppoc siH
,tniat taht gnola pu dna sbro gnignah esoht fo esab eht morf eugnot sih gniggard ylwols
.nrut prahs a no esolc rood eht dloh ot dah yeht semit emoS
tes rellams s’flow eht tsniaga yawa deppalc sllab enisru yvaeh
”...teg spin ruoy os yllihc dna ecin si kcoR gniwolB erus m’I .pu lla uoy esaerg dna lio ybab eht tuo teg nac eW“
.tahw eht tuo gnirugif ta doog yrev reven saw ayaW .liat elttil ybbuts sih delggiw dna tsehc sih ot pu sdnah sih thguorb eh nehw gnihtemos detnaw eh nehw llet syawla dluoc ayaW .gnihtyna gnidih ta doog reven saw eH
?yawa nar yeht sa secaf rieht no kool eht
,daetsni uoy kcerw I tuoba woH“
edam eh sesion eht elffum ot htuom s’flow eht otni sregnif sih gnihsup ,sleeh sih ni gud anoY ”.dab em tnaw uoy nehw ekil I“
.taes rac eht fo kcab eht ot
”.rorrim s’rac eht ni gnikool ton m’I“
,hgU“ .sehcni elpuoc tsal esoht otni kcab desserp eh sa ylleb dna edis tsniaga gnimmurd liat deppart
.gaw ot detrats liat sih sa gniralf slirtson
lamron naht ecrof erom elttil a htiw nael sih gniwener ,dehgis flow eht
gnir eson sih yb raeb eht nwod gnillup yllufyalp
.gnihtyreve dna kcab eht ni teknalb a evah I .ynop eht otni
,ruf sih rednu knip gninrub ecaf siH
,gnihgual dna kcab sih no gniyal
.doof dna tner neewteb tram-laW ta yap ot gnilliw neeb dah eh naht erom skcub 5 saw ti tub
.yawevird eht ni ylthgin tsomla ecitcarp oT .ailager sih ekam oT .siht ot pu gnidael nekat dah eh sgniht eht rof hsifles os tlef
gib uoy ydaerla em kcuf
tsehc s’anoY no daeh sih detser eh sa gnilkcac
.liat kcalb gnilggiw dna spih gnitfihs erab fo yretsym A
.oot uoy ylbaborp dnA“