.noitcerid yreve ni nerrab dehcterts dnaletsaw eht dnoyeb dna ,srekoolno fo ytpme doots pu nevird d’yeht daor ecivres eht ,woleB
.deggut dna ralloc s’teP debbarg dah sukraM nehT
msagro gnimusnoc-lla sih hguorht sborht drah neetfif ro evlewt ebyam saw eH ”!daB
.sllaw renni eht erew oS .ssalg naelc erew sllaw lanretxe eht fo llA
.sukraM s’eh swonk eh ,yadoT
.tnereffid saw gnihtyreve ,denruter I nehW
.desopxe leef mih edam siht ,os nevE
.etairporppa t’nsaw ti nehw retsaM rehtob ot ton sa os
.gnorW saw seulc esoht gnisu dna ,mih fo detnaw sukraM tahw wenk eH
.nups daeH  .deggut dna
,rotavele eldi eht ni flesmih dnuof eh dna
.llaw eht ecaf dna eldnah eht barG
.dlrowffo dedeen stcudorp weN
.deunitnoc yppuP dna ,deggurhs sukraM
ysatsce fo sdnoces wef a saw tI  .debborht kcoC .deltsirb ruF
.tey egassam ruoy
.deppir erew snaeJ
.trap txen eht rof mih tpmorp ot deen t’ndid sukraM
drawrof delffuhs yppuP
”.seye ruoy esolc ,yppuP“
dna deknilc sessalG
ot pu eson sih hsup ot egru elbitsiserri eht tlef eh dna srae sih tsap dezarg dnah A
”.uoy rof gnihtemos evah I ,ereH .yob dooG
,hctorc sih morf yawa raewrednu dna sresuort dekaos sih llup ot deganam eh nehw dna ,nettogrof saw msagro reilrae ehT
gniworg saw edis thgir sih dnA
.sdrawrof mih deirrac
.htiw nigeb ot fo rebmem a neeb reven dah—fo rebmem a
.noos ytterp edaf ll’yehT
”—saw ti tuB“  ”.retsam ,t’noD“
.elcihev eht htiw gnilaed yksuh eht ees ot denrut eH
.teef sih ot kcab mih dellup dna mih thguac mra ydaets A
”?yako ,era ew erehw rebmemer t’nod tsuJ
.ruf kciht sih hguorht shgiht renni sih nwod senil elttil dloc gnivael ,hctorc dekaos sih morf ylbeef deppird sdiulf nwo siH .tsacnwod seye
mih otni pu desserp taht kcoc kcils eht no pmub yreve wenk eH
,sih revo desolc dnah A
.reppiz sih fo reliaj eht dniheb ,raewrednu sih fo llec eht ni ylleurc thguac saw eH
”?eno laer eht s’eh taht
.dloc nur doolb 'sukraM edam
.deb sih fo swollip hsulp eht otni dehsup saw ecaf siH .delbmum sukraM
.dellup dna liat sih fo ruf tew gnippos eht hguorht delruc sregniF
.did eH  ”.yob ,ereh emoC“
?noitaitogen eht roF .ris ,notselrahC oT“  ”?pirT“
,eciov sih ot dnopser uoy esuaceb tsuj taht emussa uoY
.derobal dna deggar emoceb gnihtaerb eht raeh dluoc eh
.mih fo tuo dna otni deppils
.enola ti tfel eh tub ,dehcti tI
.ti tegrof d’eh wenk eh ,yb gnissap dnaletsaw eht deretsiger seye sih hguoht neve tuB
:snoitcurtsni erew esehT .larutan erew stcnitsnI .stcnitsni ton ,oN
.gnorw ylsuoiciled ti edam
?yppuP ot siht enod eh dah semit ynam woH
steppins elttil tsuj erew erehT
.setunim neetfif ro net naht erom on koot pirt ehT
,doom retteb sih ot denruter dah retsam sih spahrep taht gnisneS
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.tsurht eh sa gnizeeuqs dna gnihcnelc ,mih dnuora reh leef llits dluoc eH
:dnim sih hguorht derednaw thguoht eldi nA
.enoz demialcer a ot denoitisnart d’yeht dezilaer eh taht
.kcen s’yppuP dnuora ti deruces dna pu dehcaer eH
.nwod tis t’nod woN“
”.niaga noissimrep uoy evig I litnu gnihtyna ees uoy fi yrgna eb ll’I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.meht tcepxe t’nseod eh erehw ruf yksuh fo spmulc gnidnif llits si dna
.hcuot sih ta nepo gnurps rood tnorf ehT
.mih morf deppird tI
.ti hguorht mih gniees enoyna morf yaw gnol a saw eh
.tnemom a rof deppots yppuP dna ,os dias eH
.ylkciuq flesmih depmup sukraM ,slortnoc rewohs eht no llits dnah eno htiW
.rewohs eht ni semit wef a nevE
.elbativeni eht htiw elttab eht tsol eh
,hcrul nav eht tlef eH
.tnemom a rof desuap gnitsurht ehT
.tenalpruF no elbaliava si ,aipotsyd otni evled tnecer tsom rieht ,dlrowpU nwoD gnignirB
.yllaicifitra ni-tliub
.erew ”esoht“ tahw ksa ot evah t’ndid eH
- - -  ”.roivaheb tseb no
.pag detaerc ylwen eht fo tuo raewrednu sih eglub noitcere sih tlef eh dna
.ylbatrofmoc ekat ot mih rof hcum oot tsuj saw esroH .truh tI
.sriats eht pu dna teprac eht ssorca deot-pit eh ,gnippird eht mets ot hctorc sih htaeneb sdnah gnidloH
”.tep ,flesruoy rof yrros os leef t'nod ,hO“
.uoy esaelp ot evil I
.llew tpircs eht wenk eh ,llitS
.shgiht sih nwod deunitnoc egassam ehT
.tep ,retteb s’tahT“
sepirts regit htiw tac erutainim a saw enO .meht fo owt dezingocer eH
,ycavirp fo yaw eht ni elttil yrev dah esuoh ehT
.llaw raelc eht tsniaga pu htgnel drah nwo sih dehsam gnitsurht eht sa raelc yllufniap tsomla
.gnibborht dna gnihctiwt saw mih edisni pit gnitsurht taht woh dna
.sukraM saw I thguoht I ,sraey eseht lla hguorht tuB“
”?ecno siht yppup ruoy egludni tsuJ
,egassam elohw eht hguorht yldrawkwa gnittis neeb evah tsum eH .drah ylgnippirD
.efil ot gnibborht ylwols saw taht pit eht leef ot nwod flesmih gnidnirg
saw taes eht ni dna
”.kcap eht fo pot llits er’uoY
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.em rof emac tem uoy yksuh eht nehw s’tahT
,ssalg eht tsniaga deredduj eh sa elggig a ni htuom reh gnirevoc
.sdnaletsaw eht tsdima nedrag a—
”?tep ,flesruoy gniyojnE“
.dluoc yeht sa sukraM sa eb ot tseb rieht did seiksuh eht lla ,nwot nI
,oga sraey fo sderdnuh elbbauqs emos
”.emoh teg ew litnu ti htiw evil ot evah tsuj ll’uoY .tluaf nwo ruoY“
”?retsaM ,taht s’tahW“
,ssalg eht ssorca kcoc sih deraems pmuh hcaE
.rewohs eht fo roolf eht ot llef dna
,rediw sgel sih daerps eH
eldnah eht desaeler eh ,gnidnats yats ot elbatsnu oot erew taht seenk htiw dna
.snoitarepo revo ekat ot pillihP wen a enolc dluow yeht
ecaf railimaf eht ,eninazzem eht nI
.sdnaldab etalosed eht saw sihT
.delttob liaT .nups daeH
gnidnapxe eb noos dluow taht sbun mils eht erehw esab eht ta kciht yllufthgiled dna
.won saw eh ohw s’tahT .teP
.kcab sih tsniaga desserp sukraM dna
.stiforp fo sraey ythgie dnuora devlover noitasrevnoc
.gniht laer eht fo snoisserpmi elap neeb dah srewohs suoiverp sih lla neht ,rewohs a saw siht fI
.degnahcxe erew steB
?uoy t’nera ,taert a era uoy ,lleW !regae oS“
?tep ,rof gnitiaw uoy era tahW ?lleW“
gnizilaer won saw eh ohw ,derdnuh lanigiro ehT
.sukraM erew uoy wenk uoy ,oga keew A .sukraM saw I
.tnemom ot tnemom ,ti gniviler saw eH
.senifnoc thgit eht tsniaga gnislup dna dehtaehsnu tonk sih leef neve dluoc eh dna ,pit sih ot ylbatrofmocnu gnippirg saw cirbaf ehT
tnorf s’ralloc eht denroda taht gnir-
.edistuo bruc eht ot pu ylhtooms dils nav ehT
.gnidliub sih otni kcab deklaw eH
edis rehto eht ot hguorht thgiarts ees dluoc eh ,roolf dnuorg s'gnidliub eht hguorht yaw eht lla
.dwel ylsuoiciled os mees t’ndid erusopxe evarb eht ,ylnedduS
,nwo sih ot ralimis os saw taht kcoc eht ta dna
.gnitrofmoc saw ti ,llits tuB
.detcurtsni erehw tas dna
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
denepo dah srood eht nehw ti dessim d’eH
.msagro gnirettahs eht hguorht thgiarts tsurht taht kcoc eht dnuora dehcnelc yliratnulovni eH  ..deyarps kcoC
,ecnalab rof daeh sih revo tsuj eldnah eht barg ot decrof saw eh dna
,dah reve d’eh msagro lufniap tsom eht saw tI
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.luof deirc suG dna assileM elihw
.saw eH  ”.drah er’uoy
edam saw sa—dloc saw ssalg eht ,toh saw rewohs eht hguoht nevE
rewol deyarts sregnif s’yppuP .eligarf
.emac yppuP  .deggut dna
.llef eh dna ,daor eht no decnuoj nav eht ,tnemom taht tA
.ssalg eht ot talf desserp saw eh litnu ,tsurht hcae htiw drawrof mih dehsup mih dniheb ydob ehT
,sukraM ta pu dekool eH
.retsaM ,yrots a uoy llet em teL“
.mih gnilemmup saw trevlaC yaw eht ta kool dna
.tesolc moorb eht ni mih deppart dah assileM
.daor eht pu gnidilg saw nav a ,woleb nwoD .erehwesle saw
.derevihs enipS .thguac htaerB
.erew uoy erofeb ereh reesrevo eht saw I ,seY
htiw dnekeew a tneps ohw ,lerdnaK yb
.seye sih revo nwod gnitfird skcol nomannic
.thgir tsuj saw ti litnu erutarepmet eht gniretla
.mra yzzuf a dnuof sregnif gnipsarg sih ,daetsnI
.yleritne deppots neht ,denaw elzzird ehT
mih fo tnorf ni yduolc werg mih fo tnorf ni ssalg ehT
.selcsum eros otni yltrepxe dehsup dna ,mraw dna
noitnetta ’sukraM taht ezilaer ot tnemom a mih koot ti ,desufnoC
,hctorc ’sukraM no ylerauqs tas dna
.sriatsnwod emoc dna ffo yrD
.emit emos rof tnelis saw moor ehT  ”?mmh ,worromot
.ni dedoolf tnemssarrabmE
,lerdnaK yb ”emaG llehS“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.hguone tnasaelp saw taht hguohtla—
.doots eh ,noitatiseh tuohtiW
.did eh tahw yltcaxe s’taht dnA  !gaW .gaw dna
”.edir rac a tsuj s’tI
”.yas t’nac uoy tuB .wonk I ,seY“
.erutluc cilbup rehtar a ni efil elohw sih tneps d’eH
,hcuot sih ta nwod delzzird retaW
”?evitcudorp pirt ruoy saW .ris ,kcab emocleW“
.gnitaehc eb d’taht
.sllaw tnerapsnart ylsuoucipsnoc htiw osla ,thgir eht ot
.llaw ssalg eht tsniaga mriuqs dna ehtirw mih ekam ot hguone saw enola tahT
.ecaf sih revo tuo gnirettups dna gniyarps
t a ekil gnihtemos ni daed thguac eb dluow sukraM yna fi sa—trihs-T
”.taht ees lla nac yeht kniht I
”.yob dooG“  2 fo 2 traP
.dlrow edistuo eht decaf eh ,ssalg eht hguorht gnikooL
”.ereht em rof tiaW
.evalsdeb a fo seitud eht ot desunu os ,yppuP elttil yhs A ?taht rebmemeR
.won rof ton ,tsael ta rO
ereh morf ylraelc dnuorg eht ees dluoc eh taht tcaf eht tsuJ
.pmur sih degassam dna
,htgnel tcefrep eht saw ti—
.gniog erew yeht erehw llet dluoc eh ,noitnetta diap eh fi
.eldnah a saw ereht ,dias dah sukraM sa tsuJ
sukraM yltnedifnoc os saw eH
nav eht otni pu deppets eh ecnalg drawdnih a tuohtiW
.ytnewt txen eht rof snalp gniciov—sukraM laer eht—
sih no dednecsed gnihtemos ,niagA
,depahs dna gnol nworg saw daeh sih revo ruf ehT
.tnedicca roirp sih fo denaelc yletalucammi sehtolc sih
.gnidnirg tnetsisni sih ot denruter neht ,os did eH
.shgiht renni sih ssorca gnileef tew a tfel dna hctorc resuort sih ni pag eht revo delbbird ti ,nav eht fo taes kcab eht ssorca gniyarps fo daetsnI .strups yssem eht deniartser yllaitrap ylno cirbaf ehT
.htooms yltnasaelp saw noitarteneP
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.woleb nwod elcihev eht gnitixe erew taht slavirra wen eerht eht ot wohs a etiuq ekam dluow ylbaborp taht ,seY
,maertsnwod segatrohs eht fo esuaceB .detuorer eb dluow seilppus dna ,yrotcaf wen a gnitteg eb dluow gnissorC s'retraC
reltneg a dedeen retsaM—won thgir tsuj—taht gnisneS
.tlep neddos sih hguorht nwod gnipees dees ’sukraM fo senil toh eht leef llits dluoc eh tub dekaos saw ruf siH
”.thginot teiuq ecalp eht peek ytiruces evah esaelP
dluoc eh taht lla rof ,tlef tI
.llac elbitsiserri na tlef sukraM ruo
,sgel sih neewteb liat sih kcut ot egru eht dah eh dna nwod dedlof srae siH
.devivrus ylsuolucarim wohemos dah taht gnidliub a fo erutcurts lateleks erar eht rof tpecxe
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.od ot mih dlot sukraM tahw enod d’eh retfa niaga delkcub ylraen sgel siH
.niaga denepo srood dna
”?stnap ym teg dna revo hcaer uoy dluow ,yppuP“
deneppah dah tahw dezilaer sukraM erofeb
?eh t’ndah ,gniht laer eht tem d’eH
,ti ssorca dehsalps nemes sih fo stej sa
,rewohs eht rednu hctorc sih morf gnisnir ylwols muc nwo sih htiw ,gnippird dna dekaN
.gnitsurht deppots reven trevlaC
.mih rof t’nerew ti fi yaw siht gnileef eb t’ndluow retsaM
.llaw eno no lenap cimonogre na dna roolf etinarg dehsilop-rorrim htiw moor a saw tI
.deirt eh nehw dnim ot emac taht segami elttil yarts—
.dias yeht ,etunim yna pop ot gniog s’esroh ehT
.desolc srood eht htiw tfahs eht fo pot eht ta gnittis
snoitacilpmi ehT
.tac fo ylgnorts gnillems denruter d’eH
.pirt eht morf derit tsuJ“
.htaerb fo trohs tlef eH
?won ,sukraM sa flesmih fo kniht eh dluoC ?sukraM
dias eciov gnitrofmoc ’sukraM dna
wonk lla ll’ew tahw rednow I
,flesmih revoc ot sdnah sih pord dluoc eh erofeb tub ,kcab dedlof srae siH
.ni em gnikaerb nuf hcum os dah uoy rebmemer I“
,elbat eeffoc eht htaenrednu gur eht revo lla gniyarps
.mih dleh ylpmis dna etiteppa lauxes suoicarov yllamron sih debruc yppuP ,dnah
,roolf driht ytnewt eht no pu tub ,esuohtnep sih ni siht ekil wodniw a dah eH
,tnorf sih revo desolc sdnaH
ralloc sih debbarg enoemos nehT
moorhtab a saw ereht ,dias dah sukraM sA
.eludehcs ylppus tnereffid A .demoolb yromeM
.esuohtnep eht rof nottub eht tsniaga regnif sih dehsup eH .desolc rood ehT
.sroolf deteprac ylhsul eht rof tpecxe
.tew staes erom neve teg ot uoy tnaw t’nod ew dna ,ssem a fo hguone edam ydaerla ev’uoY
.revo koot yromem elcsuM ”!esruoc fO“
.htuom s’teP morf flesmih dellup sukraM
.kcab sih otno revo dellor sukraM sa detfihs yppuP
.drawer a sa ereht ti tup dah—sukraM laer eht—sukraM
,sgel sih daerps dna daeh sih evoba eldnah eht debbarg eH
”?os kniht uoY ?eno laer ehT“
.rehtael doog era staes esehT“
.won nwot fo tuo hguone raf er’ew kniht I ,yllautca—
htiw enO .reesrevo fo dnik wen a dedeen ew dna ,degnahc noitcudorp nehT
.derif stcnitsni ,desserppus dah eciov s’retsaM taht ssensuoicsnoc eht ni erehwemoS
.desrever snoitisop eht htiw tnereffid ylrettu os tey ,railimaf os saw tI
.eb dluow ti suht dna ,nekops dah sukraM
,drah neve t’nsaw teP
.eborsid mih depleh yppuP dna
.gnisaelp ylddo noitasnes eht dnuof eh tub ,siht ekil yalpsid no eb ot egnarts dna wen os tlef tI
,snwot neewteb sdnaletsaw eht ni erew yehT
sredro tcerid dna dootsrednusim sehsiw tuoba seirots esoht lla ekil t’nsaw tI
.mih dessik sukraM dna ,htuom sih denepo eH .spil sih ta deppal
ecnesba gnol sti morf denruter mih dellortnoc taht eciov eht sa
.hcuot sih ta denepo rood tnorf siH
).suG saw eman s’flow eht denrael d’eH( .flow eht dna assileM dias ,teP ton ylsuoivbO
,wols ot detrats nav eht litnu t’nsaw tI
.yllufniap tnet mih gnikam neeb evah dluohs taht ealumits on—ti rof nosaer on saw erehT .gnibrutsid saw enola tahT
.rewohs eht fo yarps eht ni yawa dehsaw neht
yojne esaelP  .sukraM
!deronoh leef dluohs uoY
.dedeen saw eH .detnaw saw eH .mih detnaw sukraM taht wonk ot erusaelp wen a saw tI
.tsej ni edam erew sesimorP
”.meht deniur ev’uoY .tep ,ffo esoht ekaT“
.rewohs eht no nruT
.hguoroht osla saw eh tub ,fo elbapac saw eh sa tneconni sa gnieb saw eH
.raewrednu sih tsniaga gnislup morf tfahs sih pots t’ndid taht tub
.yrrow t’noD .tep ,ereh m’I“
.eldnah eht no sih revo desolc sdnah ’sukraM
,kcab dellup sukraM ,ylwolS
eht tub ,yltcaxe ,truh t’ndid tI .elzzum
,seiksuh ssenisub enolc lacitnedi eerht ythgie
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,emit tsaL  .yrruFoS no
,kcen sih tsniaga drah gnihtaerb saw sukraM woh saw ssalg eht tsniaga gnilbbird dna drah mih dah yllaer tahw tub
redrah saw eh taht deciton eh taht tniop siht ta saw tI
.elzzum sih fo tnorf ni tsuj htaerb ’sukraM dellems eh ,ffo ti dellup sdnah sA
,revird on saw ereht tnorf nI
.ytilaer fo kcart tsol eh taht diviv os kcab demaerts snoisiV .dehsalf noitcelloceR
.tlep sih no thgilnus tlef eH
.snoitarbelec rieht htiw ysub erew yehT .teP fo esu hguoroht gnikam saw ehs erehw ot sllaw raelc eht hguorht ees t’ndluoc yeht fi sa detca dah esle enoyrevE
.ti enod d’eh dna ,redro na nevig neeb d’eH
.gnipacse morf pley deifingidnu na pots t’ndluoc eH
.tem d’eh sukraM yna ekilnu saw ti tub ,sukraM saw tI
.deralf yromeM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.mih dednimer dna ni degrab yromem neht tub ,saw ti revetahw ta etib ot saw eslupmi tsrif siH
.htaehs sih otni kcab gnitaerter ylkciuq dna drah flah ylno saw eh
.gaw liat sih edam tsurht hcae no mih ta dehsup dna deggut tonk gnidnapxe eht yaw eht dna
.edarmoc tsol a ekil mih ot kcab dehsur ytirohtua fo gnileef ehT .denruter eciov ehT
”?yako uoy erA .tfel uoy ecnis syad rof swen rof gnitiaw neeb ev'eW
teef sih ,deklab dnim sih nehw tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.erom teg ot nwod desserp dna
,gnisaeler dna gnizeeuqs tpek liat sih no sdnah esoht woh dna
.ytliug tlef yletaidemmi sukraM
.edam d’eh elddup eht ni gnikaos skcals ssenisub ,taes eht ni deliocer eh ,daetsnI
.mih dezilibommi erusaelp gnikcarw sa tuhs rethgit meht dezeeuqs eh ,desolc erew seye sih hguoht neve dna ,niaga deggut ralloc ehT
.ytpme saw rotavele ehT
.notpillihP fo esroh eht
.elgna niatrec a ta eb dluow nus eht ,noonretfa-dim saw tI
.repapswen pu dellor a ekil ,sseug
.efil doog a s’ti dna
”?ew od ,tnedicca rehtona tnaw t’nod eW
.teP ,doog yreV“  .teP
,yppuP“ .dekrims sukraM
”emaG llehS“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.uoy srebmemer enoyrevE
.senap eht hguorht thgil fo gnipraw eltneg eht ylno htiw
.ruf kcab sih ni selcric elttil gnicart saw dna egassam sih dehsinif dah yppuP
.ksam larutan eht gnitautnecca ,snrettap eyd yb dekram saw elzzum siH
.bmun gnileef mih tfel noitazilaer eht
”!ytrid lla s’ohw eno eht er’uoY
.doog hcum mih od dluow erew yeht erehw gniees taht toN
.fles fo ecnedifnoc a saw ereH
,lerdnaK yb ”emaG llehS“
”.retsaM ,uoy tuohtiw dnekeew gnol a neeb s’tI“
pit sih dnuora nwod dehcnelc yppuP
,sselerutaef saw ecalp ehT
,esruoc fo ,ecin saw tahT
.elpoep gnildnah rof slliks fo tes tnereffid
D eht otni regnif sih depparw eH
”?neht ,decalper eb ot gniog m’I taht kniht uoy oD“
.yllacitahpme deggurhs ohw ,sukraM ot pu seye sih dekcilf eH
.mirb eht ot mih gnillif saw spillihP trevlaC dna ,elbat eeffoc eht revo tneb saw eH
.denruter I nehw sukraM neeb reven d’I fi sa saw ti ,decalper saw I nehW
,pillihP trevlaC saw rehto ehT
.thgir eht ot sriats eht pu ,edisnI“
saw I ,oga sraey eerhT“
.thgieh daeh evoba tsuj llaw eno fo tuo dekop tI
.retsaM saw sihT .sukraM saw sihT
lufituaeb saw ecalp ehT
,edaf ot detrats msagro sih sa mih ta pu detniop assileM
eno siht piks esaelp
.eromyna sukraM toN
enod ton m’I .evom t’nod ,oN .sukraM eurt ,eno ehT .sukraM
.noitarbelec ruo rof ereh pu thguorb ev'I eno tsrif eht ton er'uoY“
nottub eht dehsup eH
,redluohs sih no flesti dial elzzum eht nehW .sukraM rof thgit saw eH .sukraM rof doog saw eH
.kcab dekool reven I dna ,did I oS
”.won meht fo yna rebmemer t’nac I tub ,os ro keew tsrif eht rof diviv ytterp erew yeht taht si rebmemer I llA
,reppiz sih desaeler sregnif ehT
,)!yebO !tiS !leeH( ecnanimod 'sukraM fo duolc eht hguorht nevE
.sukraM morf hgual a tog tahT
sukraM raeh dluoc eh ,hctorc sih tsniaga flesreh gnidnirg ysub saw assileM elihW
,desolc deyats seye sih fi neve dna
,wal eht fo rettel eht tsuj t’nsaw ti tuB  —fi os ,mraw
.dnuora demriuqs eh sa ylleb ’sukraM no gnihctiwt saw yppuP ,hguoht ,woN
.seye ruoy esolc woN“
.seye sih denepo eh ,gnisselb eht neviG
.hguorht dekop ruf nat dna maerc erom erehw seloh dah—trihs-
.deltsoj taes siH  .dab
.wodniw denekrad eht hguorht tsap demooz setsaW
.flow detlep-yerg a saw driht ehT
.devarc yletarepsed eh tahw saw ti
.enon dnuof tub stsermra rof debbarg eH
!revird a dah eH .yad yreve meht did eH
evil I ,nruter ni dnA
.tnaem dah yppuP tahw dootsrednu eh woN
.htrae erab ot deppirts dna detsalb
gnirud tuo debmoB
.sredro ruoy wollof ot doog os tlef ti ,esu fo dnik siht rof edam neeb t’ndah I hguoht neve dna ,ecioV eht dah uoy tuB
.egassam sih deunitnoc yppuP sa
.mih ta kcab yllartuen elims draug ksed tnorf sih fo
.tnemhsinup a si siht kniht t’noD
.ecaf sih no wohs ti gnittel neeb evah tsum eH
.os kniht t’nod I tub ,ecnedive yna evah t’nod I ,wonk uoY“
”?kniht uoy t’nod ,edart riaF .uoy esaelp ot
eugnot a dna ,drawrof denael eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”.esoht fo tuo uoy ees s’tel ,yob ,no emoC
.lobmys sutats a saw tI .ytimrofnoc fo toir a saw tI .sukraM llA
.on ,gnineve siht kcoc s’retsaM ekat ot steg ohw revo uoy htiw elbbauqs ot evol d’I sa hcum sa ,hO ?noitnetta sih revo thgif ot sevalsdeb owt steg reesrevo wen eht dnA“ .dehgual yppuP
wenk I ,oga raey A
”.dnekeew eht rof tep ym gnieb gniyojne er’uoy hcum woh tsuj werc eht wohs ot uoy tnaw I ,tcaf nI
”.nwod uoy bur nac I tsael yrev eht ta ,emoC
.hcihw erus t'nsaw eH .rednimer a rO
dna daeh ruoy revo hcaeR
.sllac enohp wef a ekam ot denrut dna daeh sih deddon )ytiruces( sukraM
,nwot lluf a saw ti sselnu sdnaldab eht ni tuo siht ekil gnihtemos dliub ot troffe eht edam eno oN
.retsaM ,did yeht tahw sseug nac I“
.egarag mils a otni deraeppasid dna esuoh eht dnuora detarelecca nav eht ,yltneliS
.kcen sih dnuora tif guns gnihtemoS
.tep ,og tel erad uoy t’noD“
.deralf yromem nehT
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
regnol on saw eh
”!steprac eht no gnihtyna teg t’nod dnA“
,nav kcalb eht fo tnorf ni flesmih dnuof eh ,yawa sdraug sih gnidneS
.scra elttil trohs ni tnemeticxe sih fo segdums gnivael
.gnissorc s’notnA fo notnA assileM—
.kcen sih dnuora depsalc llits ralloc eht debbarg regnif a ,desuap eh nehW
mrif erew sregnif s’evalsdeb siH
,srae sih ot tap gnivorppa na htiW
.pillihP tnerruc eht ot neppah dluow tahw tuoba deklat eno oN
regnol elihw a rof tnelis saw moor ehT
.tep doog a neeb d’eh esuaceb lla ,mih doolf ot gniog saw sukraM ,nooS
.gnihctiwt sukraM dah esu demotsuccanu morf evitisnes ylbirroh edam strap ssorca sregniF
.eb reve dluoc yeht naht retteb meht gnieb yb seimene ruoy etailimuh dna sdneirf ruoy sserpmI
.mih ta kool ot denrut sukraM
.elttil yrev derebmemer eH
.emit ruoy ekaT .ereht luferaC“
sllaw ssalg hti .ssalg dna enots htiw daetsni ereh decalper saw ellivredorB fo leets dna etercnoc ehT .tnapucco ylno
”.werc dnalsI tseW elohw eht rof tnemniatretne eht eb ot er'uoY
.retsaM ,yako s’tI“
.tnemom a rof dellats teP
.neppah ot gniog s’taht tbuod I
”.dedeen regnol on er’ew nehw su ot sneppah tahw wonk uoY
.ssalg eht tsniaga spih sih gnillor ,esaeler ni dekauq eH
,eulb ro der deraeppa dah taht thgil fo llab tfos eht denrut ssorca regnif sih gniggard dna
.t’nerew yeht gnihtyreve saw sukraM sihT
.retsaM ,em ta hgual t’noD !si tI
.skeehc sih neewteb pu gnidils eb dluow wenk eh pit toh eht rof yaw ekam ot detfil liat sih dna
.seye ruoy nepo nac uoY
”!tep daB“ .gnineppah saw—
.mih dniheb morf delley sukraM
,gniog erew yeht erehw wonk ot mih tnaw t’ndid ylraelc sukraM ?ti saw
,esuohtnep eht ot
.desolc erew seye sih tub
.mih rof ereht saw sukraM taht wonk ot tsuj retteb tlef tI
.leehw gnireets on dna
.deb eht otno dna moordeb eht ot mih dael yppuP tel eH
.sdrow eht no ni desolc taorht siH ”—was I“
,niaga emoh sih fo ecnartne ecivres eht ta mih tfel nav kcalb ehT
.ecneidua tnetsixe-non eht ot yldwel ffo flesmih gniwohs
llits hguoht ,niaga dexaler leef ot gnitrats yllanif saw eh ,retal ruoh na flaH
.gnihserfer tub gnihcnerd ,niar yvaeh a ekil saw tI
.gnieb reve rebmemer dluoc eh naht
”s’nwot“ eht sa doots taht esuoh suoegrog a dna tol euqserutcip a saw ereh tub
,mih ediseb tsuj sukraM fo ecneserp eht htiw tub ,detnaw eh tahw t'nsaw tI .ecnanossiD
.tsrif pop dluow ohW .steb gnikat erew eerht rehto ehT
,lufthgiled saw noitcirf ehT
.gnidrow eugav fo esuaceb detnevmucric ylrevelc
.devirra derdnuH lanigiro eht fo tser eht dna sukraM litnu ssensselesu ot tenalp eht dengisnoc d'ti
.derevihs sukraM ,htaenrednU
a dna ,ytilanosrep evitressa erom a
.sgerd tsal eht nwod knard dna htuom sih denepo eh ,noitatiseh tuohtiW
.trihs sih denottubnu sregnif nehT
,repsihw mih draeh sukraM dna ,desolc dehcnelc seye s’yppuP  .ecrof lluf htiw
.mih morf piy rehtona erot esirprus
.ecaf sih ssorca daerps nirg a tlef eh
,stekcop sih hguorht delfir sukraM sA
.tuons sih tih gnihtemos nehw
revihs yppuP tlef eh ,mih fo pot nO ”!yppuP“
.elims a ni pu tfil elzzum taht ees ot doog ylbidercni os tlef ti dna ,detnaw sukraM tahw enod d’eH
?tahw wonK“  ”—wonk I taht woN
,doots eh ,daetsni oS
sih denepo sukraM  ”.retsaM“
.sedir rac sseltnuoc no neeb d’eH
.emas eht llA .ssenisub llA .strihs pu-nottub dna ,selor rieht tifeb sa sresuort erow yehT .yletalucammi dehsurb dna trohs demoorg saw ruf riehT
.etalucammi saw esuoh ehT
.srae sih delffur neht ,tnemom a rof mih rof llits dleh dnah ehT
,etius sih otni delbmuts eH .t’ndluoc eH .oN
eb ot uoy tcepxe I dna ,stseug ym ot ffo uoy wohs ot dnetni I
.daB .wonk uoy ,denaelc meht teg ot evah ot gniog m’I
.snezitic teercsid sti rof nwonk t’nsaw ellivredorB
.sukraM gnieb ton elbatrofmoc saw eh taht
.tep regae na er’uoy ,hO“
.mih rof gnitiaw ,ereht saw yppuP
,evil ot teg I oS .yltcaxE“
.sruoy saw I dnA .ereh neeb syawla d’uoy taht wenk enoyreve dna ,ereh erew uoY
.ralloc eht saw ti nI .dnah
.ekaw sih ni muc fo selbbird gnivael
siht ekil depmuh gnieb fo noitasnes eht ot cificeps gnihtyna t’nsaw tI
gnieb eb d’eH .ot desoppus t’nsaw eh gnihtemos gniod eb d’eH
.deddon yletaidemmi—sukraM ,oN—teP