yreve fo scinomrah eht rednu neddih si noitalihinna fo gnos-neris llirhs dliw ehT
”.uoy kcuf annaw I“
.ssa s’xof eht ta dettaws dna wap sih desiar ognid eht ,ylhsilooF
.wap deppuc a sih tuo dees s’rewollof sih gniknird ylevitcudes dna ylwols
”.srewop xes cigam htiw subucni cainamohpmyn A“ .riap eht gnidnuorrus gof gnilriws ,kciht a
”.htiw gniyalp er’uoy tahw wonk t’nod uoY“
”.em no tumag eht nur ,no oG“
.sgel keels gnol sih
.uoy morf devomer eb lliw ycnega fo dna
.dedda dna wap sih devom eH
.dekrims ognid ehT ”.tsil eht ot taht ddA“ ”?pu uoy neffits
.taorht ruoy nwod eramthgiN naciremA eht ruop lliw I tuB
…dluoc eh ,ylnedduS .deredduhs kcaJ
.esruoc fo reittuls dna reipmiks evah I
”.gnitallitit yletulosba si si ereht tahw tuB“ .delims kcaJ
.yrrow t’noD ”.htob
.lasuora fo edit eht yb dewollaws saw lanrac eht dnoyeb kniht ot tpmetta ynA
.ot tnaw reven ll’uoy taht s’ti
,detcurtsni eH ”.em wolloF“
”.noitpeced fo dnik taht ot enummi m’I taht si ,siht …fo traP“
”?t’nod uoY“ .delims kcaJ ”…oN“
”.erusaelp lanrete uoy evig lliw I
.gnidliub eht fo sllaw eht hguorht gniohce
,derans retsamgniR ehT ”.uoy dlot I“
”?krow t’nseod cigam eht fI“
.ti fo retteb thguoht eh
,ereh thgir uoy emusnoc ot ton
,saw dratoel s’xof eht fo pmur htooms eht erehw ot htgnel s’flowerew eht gnidiug eilloc lufpleh eht
,dnatsrednu uoy sekam
.dworc eht ta ezag saw od dluoc kcaJ llA ”.ni ti knirD .uoy
,sedis lla ot ffo dekool eh sA
.em rof ereht tuo dlrow on s’erehT“
,elihwhtrow gnihtemos edam s’eh gnipoh yllaer
,deksa namrab ehT
.enola dnim sih tsuj htiw
.kcen sih pu dna tsehc sih revo
”.ti yas uoy raeh elpoep eseht lla tel dluohs uoy kniht I
,bbe ot nageb egar s’retsamgniR ehT
.ot tnaw ot nosaer a evah reven ll’uoy taht s’tI
.hguone noos sevlesmeht laever dluow retfa saw eh nosrep ehT
.uoy rewoprevo ot gniog er’yeht dnA
”diaL“ gnippiuq elihW
,snoitibihni sih gnippils yltnenamreP
,gnidaer dnim t’nsaw tahT“ .derettum eh
.delbmurg xof ehT
,deunitnoc eH ”.t’nod uoy tub
.gninnur pots ot egru nA .tsurtsid ni smoolb dna
”.ria niht otni dehsinav rekcuF“
,em dnatsrednu d’uoy wonk I dnA
.enif ,yakO“ .deffocs neht
,tsiaw s’flow eht dnuora gnipparw sgel rednels sih fo eno
”-dnatsrednu t’nod I ,yrros m’I“
nam desuora na fo swap regae eht ,depsag kcaJ
deb eht dnuora emalf fo skcil ehT
.desserppo ylevitca dna desilanigram er’uoy taht
.potrab eht no teluma egral a decalp kcaJ ”-I ,lleW“
,netfos t’ndid ezag s’retsamgniR ehT
.niaga ezag yrtlus ,kciht
s’retsamgniR ehT“   yojne esaelP
gnihtemos yrrac ot deen I oD
.ti rof ylecin os deksa dah ohw
ees dna nwod ecnalg dluow eh naht
”.sruo lla si erusaelp ehT“ spil sih dekcil
.elims a htiw dias tius a ni flow A
”.deen uoy emit eht lla evah uoY
,deb eht fo toof eht tA
”.neht wonk uoy tahw em lleT“
mih  evol ot detnaw ev’I“
.nwo sih htiw ezag yrtlus eht gniteem ,dennirg kcaJ ”.toh s’tahT“
d’eh naht erom ,rekcihT
.maerD naciremA eht uoy evig t’now I“
.yrruh on ni saw ognid ehT
,hguoht tnemom a roF
tsom taht ognid eht evig dna trap dluow tekcaj eht fo sliat eht os liat sih gniggalf
”.erolpxe ot tnaw uoy taht msagro lanrete eht fo edistuo dlrow a si ereht spahreP
,dnim s’ognid eht ot emoc dah
”.em ekil enoemos fo dnim eht daer t’nac uoY“
”.flesruoy yb lla ereh tas uoy ees ot emahS“
denetsil era yeht regnol eht dna
.ysatnaf yreve ruoy revocnu oT
,toh yllufwa tog moor ehT
taht flowerew eht evag xof ehT
ykaerf yllaer gnihtemos od uoy tuoba woH
”-a rof laem hguone doog a ton I mA“ .desaet kcaJ ”?ton yhW“ ”.t’nac I“
.letoh eht fo tnorf eht gnikoolrevo ynoclab llams a ot tuo kcaJ del retsamgniR ehT
”?stsevrah …suoiverp ruoy ot deneppah tahW“ .deplug kcaJ
.nwod deloord elttips ,decnad seugnoT
.dlrow sih fo tuo
”.thginot teiuq yllufwa si deb yM
.ygoloib s’rentrap eht retla …I oS
,lufraF lacsaP yb
”.os yas ot lufrewop enoemos fo deracs oot
”.retsaM uoy knahT“
.ytidommoc lufesu
,leef reve uoy lla eb lliw syot wollef ruoy fo esoht dna
.niaga xof eht ot resolc gnippets ,dias eH
.desucof erom emaceb sllaw ehT
,erised latnem eht ni htoB
.enilwaj s’flow eht gnola regnif a gninnur
thgirb dna der yrrehc tnarbiV
”.wonk ro ecneirepxe
.tfel eno tub si ereht litnu
.nwo s’ognid eht otni peed seye gnivrats ,gniwolg htiw gnizag dna liat sih gnihsiws ,deooc xof ehT
”.em rof tuo gnihtemos kcip ot uoy teg ot evah annoG“ .delims kcaJ
ro ynoga ni ro yrd enob eb rehtie ll’uoy dna
,uoy deef ll’I dnA
.spihc yna yub t’ndid eh
.rae s’kcaJ ni toN
.knird eht ekam ot deraeppasid dna wob a evag eilloc ehT
,wap sih ot koob dlo ,egral a gnirujnoc
”?riS ,mih evol dna mih ssik I yaM“
erew seye s’eilloc ehT
.sih ecaf ot elzzum s’retsamgniR ehT gninrut
.tsap eht fo gniht a era hself eht fo snoitatimil ehT
.tnesnoc eht tsuj ,daer lluf a
.gnihgual deppots yllanif ognid ehT
.rednerrus detaitogen a gnidnif fo tub
.etarapes ot trats lliw niarb ruoy fo sreyal eht taht
subucni na ,lla retfA
a htiw kcab dekool xof ehT
.xof eht ta kool ot daeh sih denrut kcaJ .thginot os toN
.ffo decnuob ylkciuq tub
.xof eht enimaxe ot daeh sih denrut ognid eht
.ecnatsid eht otni derats dna tuhs koob eht deppans xof ehT
.deksa ognid ehT ”?rettam eht s’tahW“ …ton s’taht …oN
..niaga deretlaf ezag s’xof ehT
.mraw nar rab eht dnuora sliar ssarb eht ,deslup sthgil ,mih htiw rrup ot demees dlrow ehT .derrup xof ehT
,revocsid lliw uoy seisatnaf eht lla dna
.hcraeser ym did I“
,retsaM otni kcab detsurht kcaJ sA
”.ereh t’nia eh ,won sruoh 01 rof gnihcraes neeb ev’eW“ ”!tinmad
.naem I kcuf eht tahw llew nmad wonk uoy wonk I“
.ysae reven si nevaeH
”.rettam t’nseoD“ ”?tahW“
.gnilims dna sgel keels sih gnissorc ,delims eH ”.xof lufyalp …a tsuj m’I ,lleW“
.wap a devaw xof ehT
- ”.taht ekil  skaerf rof sgnidne yppah on s’erehT
.revo deliot ylsseltniop
.tahpot ylevol sih dna skcol nedlog esoht
,ecaf s’retsamgniR ehT revo ylsselerac yrev os dednal dah daol sih
,lleW“ .deppils tub
.revO dnA .revO dnA .revO
,hguoht ygoloib ruoy ot egnahc a t’nsaw tahT“ .dekrims kcaJ
.yrrow ot nageb kcaJ .knurhs sllaw ehT
.teiuq yllufssilb tnew rennacs eht ,resolc evord eh sA
,tuo dnats t’ndid tsomla tiftuo ehT
.pu depip eciov A ”,riS“ ”.tcefreP“
.lavorppa taerg htiw delggig retsamgniR ehT ”?uoy erew
.eenk eht ta elkcub dna ylbidua naom kcaJ ekam ot hguone yhtliF
.secalp thgir eht lla ni tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
nemow dna nem ot seisatnaf lauxes edivorp ot deveileb si ohw xof subucni der a ot gnignoleb teluma nA
”.eciwt kniht d’I kniht ot dam eb attog ev’uoY
” .ereh teg ot tsuj spoc nurtuo ot dah I
.rehgih dna rehgih worg
,niaga ezag taht deirt retsamgniR ehT
”.erofeb daer dnim eht detsiser reve s’ydoboN“
.sruoy si eciohc ehT“
…tsuj toN .em laer eht
,nwod wap sih desae xof ehT ”!esaelP
.hcraeser suoluciteM
,meht otni erats uoy nehw ,seye lamroN
.erugif s’kcaJ hguorht dekool seno esehT
.hctorc rieht tsol yltnatsni strohs xetal s’kcaJ  ”.esruoc fO“
- ”.evila ereh attuo ti ekam kaerf taht tel t’noD“
.delims ognid ehT ”.uoy deef ll’I“
.mih ta kooL .sruoy otnI
os si hcihw taht
,rab a ot revo yaw sih edam eh ,daetsnI
.nruter ylwols stnapucco sti dna rab eht ,neht dnA
”.klat ew elihw knird a uoy yub em teL“ .dias kcaJ
”.relbmag a fo hcum ton m’I“
,derevoh retsamgniR eht
reverof gninnur dna gninnuR
”.lortnoc ekil ibucni tsom ,ddo s’tahT
gnirepsihw erofeb ,dias ognid ehT
.xof eht erofeb nwod decalp saw knird eht sa desuap ognid ehT
.gninnur peek I esac tseB
.tpecnoc wen a saw
,neerg wolg ot nigeb seye s’kcaJ
,emag eht fo daeha mees uoY“
”?ro ,uoy llet ot deen I oD“
”.flowerew a no krow lliw cigam ym fi wonk t’nod I …si gniht ehT“
,luos eritne ruoy reuqnoc ot rewop eht evah I
.daeh sih koohs eH
,unem eht no saw eh yppah ecnO
.deddon ognid ehT
”?drac DI ruoy s’erehW“
.s’kcaJ ot spil sih gnicalp dna nwod gninael
.mih rof gnitiaw saw enoemos erehw
,detseuqer sA  .reilrae
.ediw tnew seye s’retsamgniR ehT
.erusaelp ni delwoh dna delkcub eH
eman yb ti rof deksa I“ .dennirg kcaJ
dah reve ev’uoy seisatnaf eht lla edivorp lliw I
.tsal ta depsag kcaJ ”!yakO“
.desuap retsamgniR ehT
,deracs saw eh tsrif tA
,dnim fo dnuos ,sllabnroh dlo htob er’eW“
.erutuf on ,emoh on
gniyaws saw oot sih taht kcaJ detrela taht liat fo gnihsarht siht saw tI
.kcalb ot ssalg ekil srettahs dlrow ehT
.ecnatsid eht otni decar eh sa ognid eht ta stohstop koot dna teef sih ot derebmalc reciffo eht ,rac eht fo htgnel eht nwod gnulF
,lasuora eht fo ecrof lluf ehT .delims kcaJ
?thgir taht t’nsI
daeh sih kcab werht flowerew eht ,tsal tA
,ycerces yreve fo ,tiusrup
.pu nrut ll’eH .ti taews t’noD“
.esruoc fO“ ”?uoy t’now
.etinifni saw moor ehT .erom erew ereht
”!?hcum oot em emmig annog er’uoy deirrow ’nikcuf er’uoy won dna
”.tnesnoc ot dewolla eb ot dnamed I
.regnuh sih yb koob sih morf detcartsid ,deooc xof ehT
.htaed fo swaj eht otni fleseno gnilf ot egru nA
.gninepo lufesu tsom taht gnirab won saw tub
…ot demees meht fo enon tub
”.decudes eb ot sevol enoyrevE“
”.lavivrus ruoy ot lacitirc s’tI“
.daeh sih gninrut ton
.doof rof uoy laets ylpmis dluow ohw em ekil ibucni era erehT
.em tnaw t’nseod dlrow tahT“
yllanif ,yllanif dna
”.gniht eht s’taht ,t’now uoy tuB
.ecneivresbus taht eunitnoc si od ot deen d’uoy lla tuB
”.tib elohw eht od uoy tel ll’I
.tfahs gnislup s’kcaJ sserac ot nageb wap kcalb railimaf a ,yllaniF
?gniod er’uoy tahw hO“
”.ti wollof ot uoy ot pu s’ti ,wal eht uoy llet ot em ot pu ton s’tI“
.uoy saw ti taht ylpeed os hsiw ot dna
,teef sih ot delbmuf retsamgniR ehT ”…I ,od I ,oN“
”.em ”eruc“ ot em ni seldeen kcits dna emoh dna esuoh fo tuo em esahC
,spih s’flow eht morf
.elims a htiw deil xof ehT
,daeh sih dnuora detehcocir htob eciov ehT .retsamgniR ehT
.ecnatsid eht ot wap gnidnammoc a gnisiar erofeb ,derepsihw eH ”.hO“
.krow ot nageb spih s’retsamgniR ehT sa seye sih otni peed gnirats ,flowerew eht revo denael xof ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .treseD eht morf
.yawa gnidaf riap eht naht rehto sgniht lla dna
,mih edirtsa delwarc eH
.wonk I .ti tpeccA“
.ti xim ot nageb dna deddon eilloc eht dna knird a deredro eH .ognid eht fo edirts eht tlah ton did siht neve tuB
”?wonk ydaerla uoy spahrep
”.noitpeced gnieb sa ti fo thguoht reven I“
.skcol nedlog gnol revo daeh sih no detser tah pot A
”.elddif a ekil em yalP
”.subucni lufrewop tsom s’dlrow eht fo liart eht no
”.eveels ym pu skcirt artxe wef a tog ev’I taht si noisserppo eht htiw desruc gnieb rof ffo edart eht dnA“
sserac dna eldnof ,hcuot riap eht gnittel
,meht dnoyeb srewop emocrevo ot woh wonk yeht deveileb gnol evah slatroM“
.elpoep fo rebmun elbatnuocnu na saw ecnatsid eht otni dna ,elop s’reppirts egral a ot kcab sih dniheb deit smra siH
,sgel rednels ,htooms s’xof eht no swap sih gnicalp ,dias eH
”.rail doog a ton er’uoY“ -I t’nac yhW
.trihs-oduesp etihw a fo kcen eht dnuora eitwob kcalb gib A
desirammus xof ehT
,htrig taht lla ,sehcni esoht llA
”.xof cigam lufyalp a htiw ffuts ykaerf od ot stnaw ohw yug lufyalp a m’I dnA“
”…ti noitnem uoy won …hO“
yllaer si dna retcarahc eno siht gnitirw raey a revo tneps ohw
,etaf ruoy dnatsrednu uoy fi ees ot dnim ruoy daer ot gniyrt m’I yhw s’tahT
.deilper flow ehT ”.yllarutaN“
,tiftuo dna ruf s’xof eht gniporg dna gnibbur
.niaga meht leef ot gnihtyna
,reciffO naem uoy tahw wonk t’nod I“
saw tub ,ylthgirb wolg t’ndid eH
.neerg diviv a wolg ot nageb seye s’xof ehT
!?dnim ruoy otni em tel dna
,gnittif thgit elttil A
.seod eh esruoc fO
”.yalperof ti llaC“
.em trevnoc nac yeht kniht yehT
,gnidnats ot kcab delbmuf eH ”…yako yakO“
.elbapacseni erew s’retsamgniR ehT tub ,yremmihs ylriaf
.depsag kcaJ ”.tiaw ,oN“
.teluma lufrewop taht saw kcen s’kcaJ dnuora dnA
”?noitavreser ym tog uoY“
.swalc ym htiw ydnah nmad ytterp ,flowerew a m’I
,thgiled ni elttil a wolg ot demees ,deppots xof ehT
”.uoy dlot ydaerla I“
,thgiled ni demaeb xof eht tuB
.rac denodnaba eht gnikcik ,detnurg ffirehs ehT
.ton ro eb ot tnaw ew rehtehW
”-ol taht elohssa s’nam a teg ot troffe fo tol a sekat ti tuB !wonk I“
.meht evoba ti gnitcurtsnoc ylhsirevef saw cigam neerg eht tub ,dekool dah kcaJ nehw sriatspu na neeb t’ndah erehT
gnitarebil os ,lufrewop os
”.ekam ot ekil I taht snoitacifidom
”.nosaer elpmis eno rof etar sseccus hgih a hcus htiw dna ,lufrewop os
modeerf fo ,eciohc fo aedi yrev ehT
.semoceb ti elbidua erom eht ot
.detrons kcaJ ”?lufrewop tsoM“
”.yawa nrut ot ecnahc tsal ruoy si sihT“
,now yllanif noisneherppa s’retsamgniR ehT
.delims retsamgniR ehT
”.sdnim daer ot woh wonk t’ndid uoy thguoht I“
.rehto hcae
.hctaw ot nuf os ylno s’tI ,hguohT
,gnikael htgnel sih leef dluoc eH
”.dnim ym daer ot gniyrt er’uoy wonk I“
”eman ruoy wonk t’nseod taht eloh yrolg pots kcurt a t’nia erehT
.pu deird spil sih no lasuora gnippird ,kciht eht dna llef daeh s’xof ehT
.stun s’flowerew eht fo dloh eltneg a koot wap s’retsamgniR ehT
.pu dnats ot trats xof desufnoc eht dehctaw
,ytitnedi ,yteixnA
- .tops gnikrap a otni dediug eb flesmih tel dna dennirg ognid ehT
.eilloc desserd-ylerab eht ot denrut eh sa
.noom eht ta pu derats flow ehT
erised uoy gnihtyreve uoy evig ll’I“
.lasuora saw leef dluoc kcaJ esnes ylno ehT
.erolpxe ot detnaw taht swaP .dessik eb ot gniggeb
”.ehcadaeh a flesruoy evig t’noD“
”.demaerd I naht retteb neve s’ti
,ti gniyfed fo rettam a ton eb nac lavivruS
.meht tuoba sliated tnuocer t’ndluoc eh …tub erus
rewop lauxes eht tsevrah nac ohw xof subucni reeuq lufrewop a tuoba nettirw hcum t’nsi erehT
.ylreporp evom t’ndid spil siH
.em hctac reven yeht dna
.enim sa llew sa ,ekas ruoy roF .gnilaeppa
.nug sih rof dehcaer namreboD ehT
.pu til seye s’retsamgniR ehT
,noziroh eht no ,yllaniF
”.pots reven ll’uoy dna
.esoprup eht rof tliub m’I
,eciohc ta tohs a dah reven I
.riap eht neewteb ecnatsid gnittup dna gnirettahs noisiv
”,siht dnA .yrd nur yllausu …esehT“
neve ton s’ti dnA“
.llits rethgirb tey dewolg xof ehT .tsal ta depsag kcaJ
?suoitatnetsO .suoitatnetso
”.detnaw reve I lla s’tI .ti oD
.dennirg ognid ehT
…uoy ekam ot ygoloib ruoy fo strap tsujda ot deen I“
.delkcarc rennacs ehT
seisatnaf rieht peek yeht erehw sdnim rieht ni seloh elttiL“
,drawrof kcab flesmih gnigniws ot kcab yaw ,yaw kcab sih gnihcra morf tnew xof ehT
”!noisiv taht …tahT“
”.otni flesym knis nac I taht
uoy taht dna
.noom eht ot gnirutseg ,deksa eH ”?ereht taht evael I
- .noitcefrep dnoyeb saw noitasnes yrevE
.cigam sselniap tcefrep htiw peed sllab ni dils eh
.kcab saw moorllab suolubaf ,suomrone ehT
”emocleW s’retsamgniR ehT“
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
”.em esaet ,tsrif tuB“
,gnidaer-dnim deen t’nod uoY“
,retsamgniR ehT m’I ,lleW“
.elzzum s’flow eht dnuora loord eht raems ot regnif a htiw tuo gnihcaer ,doots xof ehT .redduhs ot nageb flow ehT ”…M uoy knahT“
”.meht evig uoy tiftuo eciN“
”?ekiL“ .dennirg kcaJ
.dekrims ognid ehT ”.em ruomuh …tsuJ
lleW“  .dekrims kcaJ
…revo dna revo dna revo ti pmup dna ,noitasnes eht eriw-drah uoy nehw dnA“
.srelbmag lla era klof reeuq sU
.xof eht nihtiw leud lasuora dna noisneherppa eht was kcaJ
.gnireehc erew yeht dnA .mih ta
.deedni secalp thgir eht llA
,llew def eb lliw uoY
.uoy gniggeb m’I ,esaelP“
.ylballortnocnu gniloord saw eh tuB
lufrewop os smsagro uoy esimorp I
,klof reeuq ot ti did yeht tsriF
.dias xof ehT ”.yako
,dethgiled yldnuoforP
.mih ot txen loots eht no dehcrep xof a sa ssalg sih fo noitcelfer eht ni dehctaw eH
.niaga shgiht s’xof eht revo wap sih nar dna dennirg kcaJ
,tlef sllab sih yvaeh woh
”-ti ,dratoel a gniraew m’I gnilraD ?uoy nooM“
.ti htrow eb lliw ynoga eht dna htrae no smsagro tseb eht fo eerht eb ll’ti nehT“
,elzzum s’xof eht no wap a decalp eH
,noitartsnomed fo yaw yB
,saw eh ffits woH
,dluoc eh sa drah sA .deknilb kcaJ
,pots t’nac uoy taht ton s’tI
.”eletneilc fo dnik ruo yltcaxe er’uoY“
,dnocesillim a roF ?eh
.denihw dna deredduhs flow ehT ”.won thgir
.strohs sih ni eglub eht desserac dna dehgual ognid ehT
.ylimaf ruoy eb lliw elpoep eseht fo llA“
,demusnoc ecnO“ .dias xof ehT
ni sdaol eerht teg ll’I raef I“
”.resilanrete msagrO“ ”?od ti seod tahw
…erats yrgnuh ,yrtlus
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,niaga nwod delooc moor ehT
.noitartsiger dna ecnecil srevird ym uoy nevig ev’I
”!uoy truh ot tnaw t’nod I esuaceB“
…rehto s’ereht tuB“
”.ti thgif ot evah t’nod uoY“
,dne ot ti gnihsiw ,denethgirf era yeht rehtehw tsuJ
.ytiralc ot depiw gnihtyreve
.deb eht otno nwod deppord xof eht sa kcab sih otno revo kcaJ dellor eilloc ehT
…ot detnaw dah yllaer eh fi derednow kcaJ
.ylecin hcterts dna kaerc ot nageb strohs s’kcaJ fo rebbur ehT
”?’niog uoy era erehW“  lufraF lacsaP yb ”emocleW
.mrof eurt sih htiw desselb saw eh sa thgiled ni deirc dna
etarebiL .uoy etanimod
.detanimesni ylhguorhT
.smra sih dedlof eH
.eno yB .eno yB .enO
.erehwon fo elddim eht ni erehwemos rof ylralucitraP
.em yalp …tuB .erom dna
did… ”.mih was I ecnis reve
”.kcol eht ni ylguns os stif reverof ot yek ehT
.dnuora scirbaf gnivom tsuj saw taht
”.naem uoy tahw wonk t’nod I“
?subucni na ot maerD naciremA eht fo esimorp eslaf eht rednerrus yllufeelg t’ndluow I kniht ylsuoires uoY
,ti gnitteg ton er’uoY“
”.dnah fo thgiels yleraB
.knird eht deppis xof ehT
”.sisylanatpyrc xob kcalb saw taht
sseleulav emoceb llA
,hcum os wonk uoy fi
,nwod og ot dlot saw daeh s’kcaJ
.tsiser t’nac uoy taht ton s’tI
,tsiaw eht tsap pu odexut a emaceb hcihw
”.tsrif em niatretne attog uoy tuB“
,gnicneirepxe ot desu si niarb ruoy gnihtemos t’nsi erusaelp toh etihw ,eurT“ ”?meht tleM“
msagro lanrete taht gnihcnual
,niaga ognid eht ta ezag sih detpmettaer eH ”…I“
eno siht piks esaelp
.egats a no doots won saw kcaJ tuB
.daeh sih gnuh dna delbmurg kcaJ
.noisiv rehtona ognid eht toohs ot ylno ,tsal ta daeh sih denrut retsamgniR ehT
.ecaps eht tuo llif ot dnuora gnignah elpoep sselmrof ,sselecaf htiw ,rab yruxul a tsuj saw tI
”?tuo em kees yllaer uoy did yhW“
.erom ecno kcalb ot gnihsinav moor
.denekciuq htaerb sih
,detnaw uoy tahw tsuj s’tI“
”.erusaelp gnispilce fo ecaf eht ni
.xof eht ta revo kcab dekool kcaJ ”.haey …hhu dna
,evitcidda os si noitcudeS“
.kcaJ dniheb morf erugif a fo lavirra eht decnuonna stiurf hserf fo llems ehT
…t’nac I …oN ”?gnorw s’tahW“
,niaga neerg gniwolg seye ,dias xof ehT
,delggig dna delkcac xof ehT
hcuot lufecarg ym dna evol ,erusaelp
”?ti morf kcab semoc reve ydobon taht wonk uoy dnA“
”?syug erom gnicudes tuo uoy era yhw nehT“ ”.yadot
.htrof edorts dna deddon kcaJ
evol em evig ot detnaw reve ohw nosrep tsrif eht uoY“
etaicerppa ohw elpoep A“ .daeh sih nI
.eb tsum tI .eurt saw tI
,lasuora ni tuo deirc subucni ehT
.yawyna ycnega ro modeerf
,ynoclab eht no sregnif sih demmurd xof ehT ”.em siht
tsom s’rewollof sih ni dehcnerd dna sesullahp sselecaf etinifni yb dednuorrus
”.yadot semit elpitlum tiftuo ym degnahc ev’uoY“
od d’uoy taht evitcidda oS
.snoisiv enecsbo erom htiw tem gnieb sseworp elzzum larutanrepus s’subucni ehT .lla ta gnihton saw ti ekil
.ees dluoc eh enoyreve ot edivorp ot etarepsed saw eh noitceffa dna xes eht rof
.retsamgniR ehT fO  .noisiv A
.meht yb deyortsed eb ot ylno
,ydob s’flow eht depolevne wolg neerg tahT
,ykaerf dias uoy nehw gniffulb t’nerew uoy ,kcuF“.elttil
”.noitpmusnoc erofeb stnemom lanif yrev eht litnu pu ti tcejer ot ecnahc eht uoy evig ot thgir ylno si ti dna
,tsixe t’nseod taht onisac a ot evird wef yrev ,taht ekil elpoep fo stol s’erehT
”.ylpmoc lliw ydob eht
.ylneek os daerps hcihw sgel tub
.dennirg retsamgniR ehT ”.yot dooG“
.llah onisac tsav a ot decudortni saw kcaJ
.sserpmi ot sserd ot tnatropmi os reve s’tI
.ylneddus deppots retsamgniR ehT
.derepsihw xof ehT
.tegrat sih dettops kcaJ
”?suoegrog uoy teg I nac tahW“
”.evitpecrep ylgnideecxe ton ynroh ylgnideecxe eb ot esimorp I .wonk t’nod I
.pu emac sthgil ehT
.seye s’eilloc eht saw fo eciton tsom koot eh tahw ,gnilaeppa
.daer ot dnuora kcab koob eht gnignirb ,deddon xof ehT ”.seod dlrow sihT
,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer ,lufraF lacsaP yb
.uoy rof meht lifluf nehT
”.krow fo enil ym ni tnatropmi si srentrap ruoy esaelp ot woh gniwonk
.knird sih fo tsal eht degguhc eH ”?uoy era
.uoy evig lliw I erusaelp eht naht rehto
”.sremylop tsuj s’taht ,niagA“
,yenom on tog t’nia I
,knird sih detcelloc flow
noitucesrep fo ,ssensselepoh fO
.mih esahp ot mees t’ndid sihT
.teef sih tuoba demrof dah ti fo elddup elbissopmi ,gniremmihs A
,dekrims retsamgniR ehT
.derepsihw xof ehT ”.yrroS“
!elbissopmi s’tahT .derettum eH
.dias xof ehT ”.deciton I“
.denialpxe retsamgniR ehT
,taocliat dna taoctsiaw htiw etelpmoc
”.dnuora enoyna fo tuo
lliw ecnad elop a spahreP“
rewop ym ni gnihtyreve gniod m’I“ .s’kcaJ otni thgir gnirats seye
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sespalloc ehcysp eht
,edutilos ni sworg taht ,raef
,dehcnerd ylbatius ,retsamgniR ehT
.dias kcaJ ”.seY“ ”?eh nac ,lleW“
,mih no gnitsaef erew seye dlareme s’enipluv eht woh leef dluoc kcaJ .deilper xof ehT
ni toor sekat taht egru na si erehT  .treseD eht morf
.delims retsamgniR ehT ”?devoleb ym ,seY“
gnikool lla erew yeht dnA
.uoy ta kcab kool ylno
.noitacol eht nevig
”.em ot ti evag uoY“
”.gnihtoN“ .delbiof xof ehT
”…tub ,uoy no krow lliw skcirt esoht dnA
,deraeppasid flowerew eht dleh hcihw sdnuob ehT
.niaga deredduhs dna depmuj kcaJ ”…naem uoy ,hO“
.eno etacol ot depoh eh esuaceb tsixe ylno ot demees hcihw eno
,mih gnidnuorrus selbat emag eht etipseD  .ffo gnihcterts
.dehctertstuo smra htiw gnitativel
.daeh sih koohs dna delbmurg xof ehT
.yad rehtona evil ot si teg uoy ezirp tseb eht yllamron tsuJ
,uoy emusnoc yeht litnU
.em rof dne doog on s’ereht ,ereht tuO“
.deggurhs flowerew ehT
”sdog ho...“ .etaretilbO ro
.erofeb tohs reve
.xof eht ot kcab gnikool ,dennirg ognid ehT ”.retteb s’tahT“
”?ecalp siht ni seinoclab yna tog uoY“
.daeh sih elggiw neht
.no gnignah ylerab erew strohs sih tub
.ti ksir t’nac I ,mih daer t’nac I fI .mih esu t’nac I
.wollaws peed ,tcefrep enO
.ylwols dias ognid ehT
.erofeb morf eilloc eht fo eciov ehT
deddon flowerew ehT .deksa eH ”?I yaM“
-c eH .dne dluoc sihT
”.emit elohw eht ssa ruoy ta erats lliw I ,yaw eht dael uoy fI .luferac eb tsuJ“
’sriatspU‘ .dias xof ehT ”.sriatspu ,emoC“
”.emosdnah olleh lleW“
”.retsaM ,em emusnoC“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
derujnoc d’eh koob egral eht hguorht kcilf ot detrats xof eht
,rehtona ot dednah nevaeh ees oT
”.demrofsnart I nehw hcterts did strohs ehT“
tsap nwod gniwolf tekcaj eht fo sliat eht htiw
.mih fo kool eht ekil I …eno siht won …hA
,uoy dnatsrednu I taht erus gnikam htiw dessesbo os er’uoY .ekas skcuf roF“
.teseb saw dnim s’kcaJ ,siht lla nI
.rebmahc etinifni eht fo sllaw eht morf gnar tub
”.sraey noillib a ni muc ton ev’I ekil sleef tI …I sdoG“
.tcap elbareves-non a s’tI
.em ot ti od annaw yeht won
.erof eht ot gninruter moor eht dna ,elzzum sih ot gninruter noisufnoc eht
.spil sih dekcil xof eht woh gniraeh
.nwo s’xof eht teem ot gnivom spih sih ,deksa kcaJ
flowerew eht gnimusnoc
”.erusaelp lauxes ym sevres hcihw taht dnoyeb ecnetsixe on evah uoy
.daeh ruoy ni snoisiv eseht gnittup m’I yhw s’taht
”?tahw od I d’woH“
”!skrow tI !sey …seY“
,did eh sA .dehgual kcaJ
.enog dah selbat onisac eht ,won yB
,esolc deppets eH
”?ew erew erehw ,woN“
,decnuonna eh ognid ehT
”.em ot ecneivresbus rieht htiw yppah yrev llitS
.sdrow dnoyeb …saw gnileef ehT
,demusnoc er’uoy ecno taht
.remmah eht deppord ognid ehT
.dnuora llits er’yeht hO“
”.ti tnaw ylurt ,ylurt
yas em raeh tsuj ton dna
.delims retsamgniR ehT ”.yot dooG“
,renwo gnivol sih otni muc fo daol nopu daol gnipmup
.snoisiv lauxes sseldne ni maws dnim siH
,niap fo ecnesba eht uoy evig lliw I
,pots ll’uoy ,on yas I fI“
.elttil a gniltsirb dna hteet sih ni pil mottob sih gnidloh
”?I od ,eciohc rehto on evah I nehT“
saw tiftuo ypmiks eht elihW
.ti ekam ot hsur ton tsum uoY
,delrans retsamgniR ehT
”.taht tnaw I“ .dennirg ognid ehT
.meht pu gnikcil semalf eulb htiw
;3991 ,adanaC ,dnaldnuofweN“
.tiftuo dna ruf sih otni redniamer eht bur tsuj dna
.dereens eH ”?uoy od lleW“
.tsixe ot ton demees moor eht fo sdnuob ehT
.oot uoy rof moor fo ytnelp s’ereht ,ton raeF
.scinhcetoryP  .gninthgiL
.ereht saw rood ehT
eritta s’flowerew eht ot skcos egnaro llat emos dna stoob gib ,ssenrah rehtael a gnidda
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.delworg namreboD ehT ”?esle
”?tuo em kees uoy did yhW“
.strohs xetal kcalb ynihs dna ypmiks ,thgit fo riap a rof tpecxe dekan tub-lla deppirts saw eH
.stius gniremmihs dna ruomalg
.orf dna ot ylirrem gnihsarht liat htiw ,ffits ylgnihca
.taorht sih nwod tfahs sih esae retsamgniR eht ees ot ,did dna
.ni dethgiled ,devol
,kcoc esiw enif ,lleW“
”.gnola yalp ,won no emoC“
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,tpmeknu oot saw tiftuo sih deirrow dah kcaJ
.mih dnuora morf taeh gniworg siht ot dednopser ruf sih lla woh
”.dnah ym ni deraeppa ti dna
.epyt yddad laer A
.dees sih ni xof eht fo ecaf eht hcnerd ot nigeb htgnel sih dehctaw eH .detpure kcaJ
”.uoy ot neppah taht tel ton lliw I“ .deralg xof ehT
”.em ot edutivres lanretE
.sselrewop eht tcetorp ot lufrewop eht fo ytud eht si ti esuaceB“
,detatiseh taht ezag ynroh A
.xof eht morf snaom dna sredduhs
,subucni yna tsuj ton tuB“ .detaeper kcaJ
,rewop dna yenom ekil sgniht eht
tnereffid tog s’enoyrevE“
.meht ot remmihs railucep …a saw erehT
.delbmurg retsamgniR ehT
.enigami ylbissop nac uoy naht regnad erom ni er’uoy
.raef dna yteixna fo
.tnemhsinup fo tol a ekat nac eh ekil skooL
”.si ti kniht t’nod I
.emas eht dna eno erew owt eht ,won yB
.eno ylno ylbaborp …fo enO
”?od uoY“ .delims dna
.detlit daeh sih tub
.uoy ekil latrom a rof melborp a ton s’tahT
.esle parcs a ton dna gnoht kcalb thgit a ni eilloc a
.yerp sih dnuora gnilpparg sgel dna smra
,delims ognid ehT ”.gninevE“
.gnoht xetal taht denroda llits ,namrab eht nwod deggalf ognid ehT
,sgel dna smra sih pu gnipeerc
.desaet xof ehT ”?ti si
.”traeH ylenoL a fo renwO .kcaJ m’I“
.daerht a yb sgnah lliw eerf ruoY“
;retsaM oN“ ”?ti t’nsi
woh… .dekrims ognid ehT
.knird sih deppis ognid ehT .deooc xof ehT
.ecnelis oidar tsuj neve toN
.dnoces a fo noitcarf a detsal ylno noisiv eht tub
,dedivorp maerd A .si eh yppah woH
”.onisac enif siht fo renwo
skoob wef a gnidaer taht kniht uoY“
.derettum ognid ehT ”,oS“
”.seisatnaf ,serised ,sdeen
.tnemom a tsuj rof tuo gniog erif eht
.erom ecno dloh koot ylneddus cigam citore dna taeh
”.onnud I doG“
.ngised suoromalg yllausunu na htiw ,gnidliub egral A
tsom sti ta
.uoy ot kcab meht deef ot gniog m’I
.yawa selim 05 morf tuo mih kcip dluoc ognid eht tuB
.setaropave fles fo esnes ehT
.egaP yrruFoS sih no
”.meht tlem ot sdnet tI“
.derepsihw retsamgniR ehT
.tius suolubaf a otni degnahc neeb d’eh taht
,delims xof ehT ”.emoh emocleW“
ehT fo egde eht ,mlaer eht fo egde eht ta gnikool ,ynoclab eht no denael eH
ognid ehT ”.emit ruoy gnitsaw rof esigolopa …I“
,psag dethgiled a delfits xof ehT
.gnilaeppa sdnuos tahT“
,spets dna srewot elbram ,meht dnuorA
,ytinrete fo lla roF
.stcartnoc dna sdnapxe moor ehT .ecaps eht sdnapxe dna sesserpmoc gnihtaerb s’retsamgniR ehT
peek tsuj ot demees sgniht
.ti koohs neht ,daeh sih detlit
otni gnitteg er’uoy tahw wonk uoy taht wonk ot deen I
,esruoc fo ,hguohT
”.uoy gnitcepxe neeb ev’eW
”.evitcidda …si gnicudeS“
,lufyalp dna yoc eb ot deirt taht yaw a ni ,detrons xof ehT
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.smsagro 3 tsrif eht retfa struh dna sehca yllausU“
.nwo ym fo skcirt evah I ,yllarutaN“
seisatnaf dna serised ym dnif ll’eh yllufepoH
.yoj dna eelg htiw cigam s’ti gnimoclew
llahS“ .niaga ecnatsid eht otni ffo dezag retsamgniR ehT
”.gnatsuM a gnivird ,041-I fo ffo dnuobtsew tnew eH“
,semalf neerg ni depolevne ,retsamgniR ehT
erehW“
,yteltbus ni efas ylno er’uoy fi ,gnilraD ?ioM
,etadpu na emmiG“
”?…esuaceb ”tnesnoc I“
.hguor dna emosdnah ,giB
”.esaelp adaloc anip A“
.tnemevom htiw dekaerc ylbidua
.deltsirb ruf siH .dennirg kcaJ
.dlrow eht ni eno nmad tseb eht er’uoy
misicetorE .xetal gniremmihs ,ynihs ni llA
”.em nooM“ dehgis kcaJ
”…tsiser nac I gnol woh wonk t’nod …I …I“.xof
,ruf sih lla gnirucsbo
.kcaJ ta dennirg xof ehT
”.esu lanrete rof elbatius
.detrons xof ehT .deksa ognid ehT
em dlot ev’uoy llA .t’ndid uoy oN“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tnemegduj sduolc lasuorA“
”.etis lairtsudni denodnaba na ta derevocer si
.em dnatsrednu dna yrt ot desuap t’nia uoy taht
.dias tsuj elpoep gnihtemos saw ti ekil
.seuc lacisyhp eht ni erom tub
,gnidliub eht gniretnE
”?knird retsamgniR ehT seod tahW“
.dias retsamgniR ehT ”.yllaniF“
,dehcterts seye sih sa raf sA
.dias ognid ehT ”.era uoy ohw wonk I“
,spsag lacov duorp ,duol gninrae
,serised llits dnim eht fI
.nosillE kcaJ retsiM ,hA“
…yas ot gniyrt er’uoy drow lufituaeb yrev a s’erehT“
,tibah fo tuo tnesnoc eht daer dnim dna yrt xof eht dehctaw eH
.dekaeuqs xof ehT ”?taht teg uoy did kcuf eht
,ztilg ,selbat teuqnaB
.rellams emaceb moor ehT
.ysatnaf saw tahw ,laer saw tahW
.enigami ylbissop nac uoy naht rewop erom htiw enoemos htiw gnilaed er’uoY“
eriseD .uoy tnaW .uoy
dnim sih kcurts yrrow eht dah renoos on tub
.flowerew eht htiw spil kcol ot nageb neht ,spets yrrem owt koot eilloc ehT
”.elap dnoyeb srewop yb demiam dna truh eb oT
.ognid eht ot revo kcab ylevitcudes deyaws xof ehT  ”.yletarepseD“
,elpoep ynam erew erehT
.koobeton llams a tuo dellup ognid ehT
”.tuo skael ti nehw ecin skool …tsuj tI“
?kaerts evissimbus A“
eht sA ?uoy t’nod ,taht wonk uoy
…tuo krow t’ndid siht fI
.htgnel gniworg s’kcaJ dnuora wap a gnisae ,dedda xof ehT
,sgnikram-kcos kcalb ykni diviv dna ruf etihw latsyrc
,pu dees eht fo emos kcil ot gnitrats
,dewollof kcaJ dna deklaw eh sA .weiv gnisiteppa
em hctac yeht ,esac tsroW
.detnurg retsamgniR ehT ”.tniop eht ton s’tahT“
,xof eht nihtiw knus saw kcaJ sA
.rrup dna thgiled ni kaeuqs ot xof eht gnisuac
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
”!?taht od uoy d’woH“
.detsisni retsamgniR ehT
.erew stun sih yvaeh woh leef
,gnidliub eht ot pu evord eh ,ylsuoituaC
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.deb klis egral a ni gniyal erew eilloc eht dna eh desilaer kcaJ
”.taht fo yna evah em ekil elpoep tel t’nod ereht tuo elpoep ehT
.dnim s’kcaJ otni derettu retsamgniR ehT
.nommoc ni tib riaf a evah I dna uoy esuaceB“
.tuo tnew sthgil ehT
,esnetni os emoceb lliw erusaelp eht gnol oot erofeB
”emocleW s’retsamgniR ehT“ saw sihT     …detas reven si
?taht wonk eh seod htrae no
.od ot kniht nac uoy lla si em gnirusaelp
,noom lluf eht otni dezag eH
.flowerew a rof dlrow on t’nia siht taht uoy llet I nehw em dnatsrednu ot evah uoy tuB“ .dias kcaJ
”.taht yas dluoc uoY .seY“
,dratoel kcalb a otni ylthgit yrev dettif
.ylduol gnikaerc strohs ,depsag ognid ehT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.seye s’retsamgniR ehT otni dezag kcaJ
85 dna 92 neewteb
steknirt wef a gnitcelloc dna
.seye gniwolg s’xof eht otni kcab gnikool yllanif ,depsag eH
.uoy eerF .uoy ruoveD
?tegrof eh dluoc woH .doog si gnissiK
,deloord elzzum sih woH
.knaps tnanimod ,mrif A
.elims a decrof neht ,dehctiwt ognid ehT
.erus ,xelpmoC .yleerf nevig
no gniht siht htiw msagro eveihcA“ .dias eH
.delims dna dloh sih desaeler xof ehT
.dehcterts sehtolc sih dna werg selcsum siH
.thgiled ot detnaw taht eugnot A
”?ot tnaw reve enoyna dluow yhW“
.dias flowerew ehT
strohs xetal sih woh erimda ot gnisuap ,teef sih ot tog kcaJ ,gninnirG
.hgis a dehtaerb eH .daed yletelpmoC
”.erusaelp etinifni ssecorp ot selggurts dnim namuh eht …sey hO“
.noziroh eht no elbisiv yllacisyhp ecneulfni s’retsamgniR
.ssenilenol fo dna
.gnidne doog a si sihT ?sihT“
,elggig tniaf a fo dnuos eht ta dehctiwt rae sih
.ti hguorht gnikcilf dna cigam neerg yb dednuorrus
.ria eht deffins namrebod ehT ”.reciffo ,onisac A“
,tuo dezag dna daeh sih desiar retsamgniR ehT
.tsal ta dennirg kcaJ ”?os taht sI“
.niaga devlossid moor ehT .dettorf skcoC
,yllacisyhp ,ereht erew yehT .eye eht ward
.degnahc saw tiftuo s’ognid eht ,yltnatsnI
.lasuora fo dioved ,dnim fo raelC
taht od ot dnim ym daer ot elba eb ot deen uoy dnA“
dnatsrednu ot tog ev’uoY
.detaeper kcaJ ”.tnesnoc I“
.rof epoh reve dluoc I efil tseb eht eb lliw xes ot detacided efil A
”…kcuf…uf hO“ .niaga sllab s’flow eht fo dloh gnikat
.detsisni retsamgniR ehT
”.ti tuoba wonk ll’uoy ,ti tnaw t’nod I fI
”.demusnoc eb ot snaem ti tahw dnatsrednu dna wonk uoy taht si tniop ehT“
,etilop ylno saw taht rof ,geb ot deirt eH
.deretlaf ylwols ti hguoht
.daeh ruoy otni yaw sih mrow ot subucni na tnaw uoY
,mih dnuora raeppa ot gnitrats arua lacigam eht
.emocerp htiw gniruop
gnihton fo wonk ll’uoy taht
.did eh esruoc fo taht desilaer eh neht tub
”?ffo kcab ot uoy desuac tahW“ .detcartsid eb ot t’nsaw kcaJ tuB .tsaf yllufwa
.yadot meht fo riap a tem ev’uoY“ dias xof ehT
.seisatnaf ruoy wonk I“
”.rof ereh emac I tahw s’tahT“
elbissop sa ylittums sa dias xof ehT ”.ytilaiceps ym si tnemniatretnE“
.os did eh sa wap a htiw htuom sih gnirevoc