,drib taht m’I dna
.ylevitaicerppa snaorg eh sa tib a gniffup eson
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
tsuj s’ti dna derit tsuj m’I rehtehw yas ot drah s’tI
yks eht hguorht em llup dna hsup ot gniyrt
”.klat ,yob etib annog t’nia I
,tekcaj dna trihs eht nehT
.kcab ym dniheb dna raeb eht fo ffo sdnah ym gnillup
.nwod gnidael dna ni gnidael
.sthgil rethgirb ni ytterp yrev kool ylbaborp yehT
.gnitivni tub y-nootrac
,mra sih gnola pirg sdnah ym dna sgnaf ym erab I
.tog I gniht nmad tseifmoc eht s’ti tub
.kcab s’regit eht fo trap tnacav eht gnola nur dnah sih gnittel
,redluohs ym gnola meht depard eh nehw gniht eno saw ti ,yvaeH
,tser eht wollaws t’nac-
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,meht llems nac I yaw eht tuoba kniht t’nac I
.sgnihton derepsihw ,seidob
…storrac dedderhs ,sdees emases ,srebmucuc ,ecuttel grebeci tsuJ
ekil ni dekcus s’ti erofeb
dna tcirtsid htneetriht a teg ot gniog er’ew ton ro rehtehw
”?cisum wen yna no gnikrow neeb uoy evaH“   .sseug I
,dlofdnilb a sa llew krow yllaer t’nseod ti
.efil laer ni seod ti ekil tsixe tsuj ylpmis tonnac ,txetnoc siht ni ,retaW“
,em no mrif dnah  a
,rethgit em gnippirg si raeb diaS
,em sediseb gniklaw
,yltneg em ot syas eH
,ybraen serots lareneg elttil yecirp emoS
,kcen ym fo kcab eht gnola sessik eh sa rae ym ni sgnir eciov s’regit ehT ”-retae ykcip
.ylsselemahs eil I
,neercs s’enohp ym no 90:4 a ees I ,moor ym kcol I
?gnihtemos ro egelloc ni uoY
,tahw dna swal gnikaerb ,gnissapsert
,rehtegot yalp taht no dekrow yehT
.gnihtolc fo elcitra etirovaf ym revo lla muc sih esaeler dna naorg em gnittel
,flesmih ta gnihgual s’eH .kcuF .kcuF .kcuF
.enihw delgnarts a evig I
,raewrednu ym ni tops kcils gnissarrabme eht gniciton ,snaej ym fo tuo gnileep m’I ,gnippirts m’I
”?etal tuo er’uoy wonk ehS
.gnola em gnillup
,mih tsniaga pu esolc  leef I
.muh eht hguorht naelc gnittuc tsomla
.kcab sedils htgnel evissam taht erofeb
,ti wollaws ot raeb t’nac I …I
,tnorf ym revo cirbaf railimaf yrev ,yrev a leef I erofeb spots tub
.resolc ni em gnidiug wap yvaeh
,elttil a llaw eht morf kcab em llup sttim sih sa gniksa ro mih gnippots fo yaw on evah  I
,em no wap driht a leef I erofeb eciov htooms s’regit eht raeh I
,sseug I ytterp erew hcihw ,snretnal eseht rednu lla ,srenid ,sefac
,semag rehto ni sah dna ,dluoc naeco evissam a fo shtped eht erehw ,ereH
,gnikrow s’eh tub
.ereh netfo dnuora mih nees ev’I
,hguoht.enola em gnivael ton s’raeb ehT
,ereh tuo s’eh snaem taht dna
.ffo flesreh tuc tub detrats newG ”-hcaasI“
.esuoh rebilaC eht tsap ,s’xoN eht tsaP
,teertS nneF otni kcab llaf ot gniog m’I
,elcatsbo na sa enadnum sa neve
.sbro kciht ,yvaeh fo riap a otni gnihsam spil
.ytiniffAruF ta
,drib dekan eht ta kool I
.yawa gnikool ,dessorc smra rieht
.trofmocsid gnihcrul a leef I sa drah msaps em gnikam
,em rof gib oot yaw saw ti nehw ti tog I
…dna reivaeh hcum saw llems eht
,oot ylhguor ti htiw  ecaf ym sbur eH
,ydob ym hguorht gniruop ,ezeerb a
.ti pleh nac I fi efil ym tuoba tihs mih gnillet ton m’I
”.pup ykeehc a er’uoY“
”?krowemoh ruoy s’woH“
,shtaerb peed ,yako s’ti
,em tsniaga ni dehsam era sbro deniats sih litnu gnihsup
ysmulc dna kciht si eciov yM ”-tiaW“  .htob
,kcils saw eh ttuB ?renaelc llew
.meht ffo ti hsurb ot gniyrt
.nepo htuom ym xaoc ot egnih eht ta gnihsup sregnif dna bmuht yvaeh
,pu gnivom ecnis reve dna
.taorht ym ni pu gnillew gnihtemos leef I
,trihs a s’ti ,ysmulc s’tI
?drayevarg …rO ?driht
?huh ,taht fo duorP“
.tem tsrif yeht nehw saw ti kniht I
elttil a lrans I
,noisnapxe siht ni tub-“
”?uoy ot ti s’tahW
.daeh ym tsniaga yldrawkwa rae na gninnip
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.egasiv retawrednu suoegrog   siht hguorht gnipeews yltneg cisum lufecaep eht tsuj ,sserts oN
…neeb s’ti dna mih htiw ereh pu sraey owt neeb s’tI
,mraw ylsuoitcefni si ydob siH
,esuoh eht fo edis rehto eritne eht no er’yeht dna ,ecnartne rood kcab eht yb thgir m’I
?evissergga ton s’ti  …ti dna
,gniht siht ni erehwyreve og I ,nrow lleW
,em revo muc gnibbur
,ni sdop rae ym teg I
.tihs a evig t’ndluoc dna ereh m’I wonk yeht fi llet ot drah s’tI
,tnemom a rof ylno tub ,sgel rieht neewteb espmilg dilos a em sevig tca ehT
.noisserpxe gniralg ym revo gnikaerb cinap eht
,tsetorp ot htuom ym nepo I
,tnemom a rof kcab gnillup s’eH
”-doog leef em ekam ,nom’C
,oot tnemtnahcne na ot eud retaw rednu ehtaerb nac uoY
.ria gnimmuh ,nepo eht ni teef ym kcik I
”.mM“  ?segassap terces htiw snoisnam dlo esoht ekiL
,hsuhs gnizinortap rehtona teg I tub
,yas ot tahw fo erusnu smees raeb ehT
tuoba sekoj dna setodcena dna stiuS
.llits gnidnirg ,siht ta srekcins raeb ehT
,elbissop sa elbitcurtsedni sa eb ot edam si gnidliub yreve hcum ytterP
,heheH“  .niaga em dnuora mra na tog s’eH
.repeed gnihsup erofeb eugnot ym  fo kcab eht otni ylsuollac gniggid sbrab sih
.niaga gag ot trats I litnu peed gnitteg
.gnihton si ereht os
,sllaw eht  tsniaga kcab em smals ylneddus wap rehto siH
,looc ti yalp dna yrt ot
.neercs ym no cennef desuap eht
.snaf eht raen ,ereh nwoD
,gnihtyna naht erom hguoht
.cisum ydoom ,driew ym ot gninetsil
,pu em gnillup era sdnah siH
”.dnuora kcab uoy evah ot evoL
,azzip nezorf evilo kcalb ,seirf otatop teewS
”.eiteews gar eht gnirb
,ecalp ni em seldarc yllacisab eh sa kcab ym gnola edils htgnel yssem sih leef nac I
.stekcop ym otni sdnah ym gnillup ylkciuq
.seenk ym no m’I …I dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yadrutaS litnu em tsal lliw ti fi dna
,daetsni kcen ym fo kcab eht ot gnivom wap sih
”…dik s’ydal ecin taht tuoba gniwonk enoyna tnaw t’noD
.dik ,deb a t’nia sihT“
?od I fi emoh em ekat eh lliW
s’ti taht suoicerp dna lufroloc os yllausu si ytic siht ni tcirtsid yrevE
,em ot nwod sklat eh sa neve
,ytpme llits era sesuoh eseht fo tsoM .eno tsewen eht
,drah ni gnidnirg s’regit ehT .evom t’nac I
…tsuj I tub esaelp I sa od ot dewolla m’I dna tluda na m’I snaem taht ekil
.t’ndluohs I erehw ,ereh og I tahT .serac …eno on
,doog sleef tsuj ti dna
,eniuneg os smees elims siH
.em tep yltneg seno reggib eht sa thgit ni gnippirg
,hguoht snaf eht ot esolc sihT
,dniheb ni spets eh sa kcen ym fo koorc eht gnola kcoc gniloord sih gnitser
.swap ym ot gnignilc ,ruf ym ni
”.ffuts IDIM tuo erugif ot gniyrT“
.yradnuoB eht tsap   morf ni gnillup sretsiwt tsud esoht fo eno ekil
,semag esoht fo eno fo yasse eht ni egatoof llor-B eht fo thgis gnihctac
…emos s’ehs ,naws siht hguorht gnikrow neeb ev’I
.ylbirret gnipeels morf ffits si ydob ym dna etal s’tI
.yrgnuh leef I
,tcirtsid suirauqA eht fo steerts enitsirp ,ytpme eht hguorht stuc ti tuB
.sgniht gnimmuh yltnatsnoc ,evissaM
,gninnirg llits s’eH
.roolf dnoces eht no pu
.won puc ytpme ylralucitrap a htiw yllis leef ton ot gniyrt
”.ttum gnissapsert a rof yhtuom yllufwA“  ”-emoh em klaw ot evah t’nod uoY“  .driew sleef tI
”?eman ruoy s’tahW“
.ffo skcab dna eciton ot smees eh tub
,em no dnah a leef I ”?dik ,hu yeH“
,ot toh oot s’ti litnu
.elzzum sih no smrof reens A ”?gnisiurc
.yllauteprep seitic repus owt tsal eht dnuora gnignilc mrots ytsud ,ykrum eht
,mubla reh esuap I
,siht ot thgiew laer a sdda eH
.flesym pots I ”-urC“
”.yob ,no emoc ,gnikeep oN“
”?yob ,tihs toh er’uoy kniht uoY“
tneler I sa dnuow eht ni tlas sbur tnemmoc ehT
,em gniyojne …s’eH
.ereh nwod eno on gnipleh t’nia seman
su gnitcennoc erp
,em htiw sah eh ecneitap mrif fo dnik eht gnisol reven
,mih ekat ot em noitidnoc ot gniyrt s’eh ekil
.mih tsniaga ecarb em sleef eh tnemom eht  llaw a ot em gnillup s’eH
.ruf ym selffur dna worb ym sessik eH
?eman gnissarrabme fo dnik emos mih gnillaC ?gnignilC ?gniyrC
.eet yarg gnimussanu ytterp a ,ti ta skool eH
,em no sucof attog tsuj …uoY
,mom ym htiw ,ereh pu ,efil elbats a ni eb ot yppah yreV
,pu nworg a m’I ekil ti yas ot detnaw I ,yako …I
,tops teews eht otni em gnidnirg
.dnuorgkcab eht ni no evah I oediv eht ot noitnetta gniyap flah ylno m’I
.elkcuhc flah fo dnik llits I
.tib a tuo gnikcab neht
,tuo sedils eh sa nihc ym rednu tekcaj ym gnildarc s’eH
,retaw rednu em ta gnipmuht s’ti ekil sdnuos ti ,dexim s’ti tub
I sa ereh noitisop ym tuoba kniht neve t’nod I
,etuc er’uoy ykcuL“
.ruf kcalb ,yggahs ym hguorht ylsseltroffe gnitfis ezeerb
”.rennid rof emit s’tI !hcaasI“
,segassap leets eht hguorht nwod egassap ehT
htiw elpoep doog
,tnorf ym nwod gnikar dna gnihsup swalc llud
?etisoppo eht fo dnik s’eh ,yldneirfnu ton s’eH .egnarts
.raeb nworb yltrop siht s’ti dna pu kool I ,sevolg kciht
,redluohs eht yb tib a dnuora em gnillup s’eH
,ydaets yltsom si eciov siH
,elzzum ym no si wap taht dna
.siht rof neve
,tsetorp ni naorg a evig I
.kcab ym no dnah a stser eH
,reward ksed ym ni tfel evah I ykrej hcum woh etaluclac I
”.yoB ,uoy teem ot dooG“
.hteet ym ni thguac
,txen gnittih era sdnuos eht ,gninaom ,htaerB
.niaga evoorg raluger a otni gnikrow
”.emit doog a rof gnikool eb thgim eh dias eh ,ebyaM“
,gnafecI yb uoy rof daer ,anueL yb
,naorg deyonna na sevig drib ehT
,em gnibbud s’eh ekil
.niaga mih ees ll’I woh gniwonk fo yaw on
.ereh eciohc thgir eht wonk I
,eciohc elbisnopser ehT
”.tey dediced t’nevaH“
.esion a tuohtiw dnal I
.dnah ym ni kcits a evah I
,enobralloc ym nwod ,erehwyreve …s’tI
.htmraw tew ,gnirettalps fo gnileef a ot esnopser ni
.detum tub gnizilatnat era senotrednu rehcir eht
,gnihtyna redisnoc t’nac I
.sdalas degakcaperp esoht fo eno
.flesym ydaets I sa mih  no nael em stel eh tub
.woleb morf ti gnippihs ecuder ot retaw fo pord tsal yreve rof detcartxe
,daeh ym dnuora yllufitud ti gnipparw s’eh tub
.pleh rof ksa syawla nac uoy wonk uoy …uoY“
.dnuorgrednu tsuj si siht taht driew
ti dellac eh dna ecno ymereJ ot ti dewohs I tub
,laer a sah ehs won tuB
.yhtaerb elttil a
…resolc gnimoc ,ti leef I
.yllaer eussi na neeb t’nsah ti
.naoJ elttil rof doof ybab fo raj ssalg elttil a gniraperp s’ehS
dna revo dna revo dna revO
.kcab gnikool ,siht ta srekcins raeb ehT
,yletanoitceffa em gnittep
.trihs ym no ,ecaf ym revo
”retaW fo noitaerC ehT“ saw sihT        .yob doog A
.seilimaf elbisnes dna sreerac tnatropmi
.raeb eht ot kcab m’I dna
.yltneg smra ym gnibbur swap s’regit eht
.hcum os gninnur neeb ev’I
,neht kcab trams ti deyalp neve I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.revo koot eh ecnis  sgel sih revo ylsuovren depsalc fo dnik tsuj neeb evah sdnah ym taht  rebmemer I dna
.sdoprae ym ni xim eht otni gnideelb s’ti taht ria eht ni yvaeh os s’ti esolc siht tub
,em ni kcab si raeb eht litnu ti od I eciton neve t’nod I
.nisaB fo steerts ytsud eht hguorht gninnur m’I
,ten eht dnuora gnicnuob ffuts s’yug terref driew siht nees ev’I
,ti ekat t’ndluohs I
,ruf ym otni ylikeehc gnikop sbrab
.yltnasaelpnu nruhc hcamots ym sekam taht ti fo noitseggus erem eht ro llems eht s’ti fi llet t’nac I
,nwod gnittis erofeb poows llef eno ni ti fo flah gniknird
”-wonk uoy ti rof htuom eht tog t’nia yeht
?dnim ym ni kcuts tsuj s’ti sseug I dna ”ydoom“
,sedalb naf elbisivni eht hguorht
,eson ym ni yvaeh ,tsrow eht s’ria eht erehw ecalp eht s’tI
.tnemtnioppasid xuaf suoivbo yrev  ekil sleef tahw ni
.tuo trulb I ”.91 m’I“
”~yoB ,naelc dna ecin …ti teG“
,pirg sih htiw mrif sa ton s’eH
.evisneffoni dna eltbus saw ti tub ezilaer ot tnemom a em sekat tI .muc teews
,mih fo ffo dna pu flesym evohs dna yrt I
ta tekcaj ym ssot I sa neve siht tuoba gnikniht peek I .gnihtyna naem ot evah lliw siht fo enon …siht fo lla …siht dna ,gnihtyna yned dna emoh nur dluohs I
.hcum oot gnirats m’I .gnirats m’I
.em ni mih leef ot
.revetahw ro tsol saw eh tahT
.nwod gniwols t’nera stsurht sih tub
…dna ,sllab dna kcoc sih neewteb
.cilbup ni taem gnitae htiw yawa teg neve t’nac I taht yas ot detnaw I ”…hu I“
.ecalp siht fo tuo kaens ot si ti ysae woh ecraf a tsomla s’tI  –  .dlihc doog
,kcoc rehtona gnileef
,loohcs hgih ni raey a kcab dleh eb ot drah eb nac ti …I
.tsaeb laref emos ekil em gnittur ton s’eh tub
.tsuj m’I os gniod m’I tahw aedi on evah I
.elpmet ym gnola bmuht a gninnur
.em tsuj s’ti neht dna …neht dnA
,latem fo ssam siht ta gnirats m’I
,raeb eht sa gib sa t’nsi …eH
,em skrow eh sa elttil a gnibborht s’eH
,revo gnippets dna stsirw ym gnippirg won regit eht
?thgir ,ytitnedi ruoy tcetorp ot deen tsuJ
”.noitidnoc revo emag a sreggirt taht tip a rof txetnoc ro
.stsurht regae  ,wollahs ,redrah gnipmuh
,elttil a gniggag m’I kcuF
.azzip eht hguorht yawflah ydaerla ,pu kool I
,siht ta selkcac raeb ehT
,ylreporp nepo ot woh
,lufyalp enot sih
.ni sehsup eh sa eugnot ym gnola gniraems muc sih
,newG reh gnillac detrats I nehw s’ti
.yenom ym pu gnivas ,loohcs hgih otni gnitteg edam I esahcrup a saw tI
ti ot gnignilc yletarepsed ytidimuh
.nehctik eht ni newG raeh nac I  anueL yb
.semoc eh litnu em otni erom dna erom kael mih leef nac I
.roiretxe ffurg esiwrehto sih morf gnimoc
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
t’nod I .dnuorgkcab eht ni elttil a rekcins regit eht raeh I
tuoba gnihtemos dias taht reilrae ngis a fo espmilg a thguac I kniht I
.tnatropmi ylevarg t’nera taht sgniht tuoba klat enoemos gniraeh
,yzoc ylsseltroffe tsomla mih edam thgiew artxe sih lla
.kcart gnikcab eht htiw emit ni elbat eht no yldi walc ym pat I
.deb ni yal ot evah I won tuB
,hguoht dloc lla s’ti
.ereh nwod mrahc detaruc on si erehT
,dnuorg eht ot enil tcerid a evah I ekil sleef ti
,emit a ta tib a em otni gnikrow ,skcor eltneg em gnivig s’eh sa …neht dna
,tneduts etirovaf sih rehtie m’I
,repmah ym fo mottob eht ni meht tup ot evah I
,ni kcab gnihsup s’eH
.em htiw yot ot seunitnoc raeb eht sa gnirekcins regit eht raeh  nac I
,retfos si eciov siH ”?yug weN“  .em ot
.em gnihsup t’nsi eh tub ,srekcins eH
.emit eht llA .yltnatsnoC
,gnafecI yb daeR
?thgir ,looc er’uoy meht wohs ot evah uoy …uoy
?ydaerla em ni saw hcum woh tsuj-j …tsuJ
,ria eht ni yvaeh si hgual siH
er’yehT .snaf eseht ot esolc teg em stel tI
,pu naelc ot siht esu ,ereH“
.meht tsioh ot sdnah htob deen I ekil sleef tsomla ti taht hguone gib ,ruf yvaeH
”-ekohc annog ton er’uoY
.éfac eht fo renroc yzoc eht ni
?thgir ,retteb s’tahT“  -kcuF
”?taht ekil regnarts a ot klat ot uoy hcaet mom ruoY“
dees rettib ,gninrub
,eciov ym gnisol m’I
.htiaf eht dleh htob yeht taht
,htuom ym ni erp rettib
.yad sih fo thgilhgih eht neeb sah siht ekil
.meht revo epard ti gnittel
,em no gib elttil a llits si …tI ?won tub
,gnitsiser m’I
.rewol dna rewol nwod
,og em tel ot gnivom
.daeh ym ffo trihs ym sllup raeb eht sa
.gninrom eht ni rewohs eht tuoba gniknihT .deb nI
,elttil a trihs detniat ym gnillup s’eH
.ecin tlef pup flow elttil a ni gnikat peehs a tuoba stnemmoc dna sekoj yseehc reh nehw elttil saw I nehw emit a rebmemer I
.ffo raelc trihs eht gut mih pleh dna
,em no mih leef I dna
.elzzum ym gnola ,trihs ym otni
,elttil a ffo skcab llits eH
.ti raet ot gniog s’eh kcuF
,nepo em gnidaerps llits s’eh
.yoB ,sdoog eht no sdnaH“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,rorroh gnikaerb-dnim fo ecruos a neeb
.tsomla ruf ym otni muc eht gnibbur  …ro …gnipiw
,niaga tsud pu gnikcik ,spetstoof …tsuj
?erehwemos em gnikat s’eh fi ro tsol er’ew fi ro etal
,mih tif ot ediw nepo ot evah I sa neve
,nepo htuom ym gniyrp no kcab si ttim yvaeh s’raeb eht tub
,gnola gnimmuh tsuj
.tsomla mih otni gniknis
.reh gnillet morf mih pots ot evah I
,shtap fo krowten gnilwarps A
,taolfa su gnipeek snaf eht fo eno evoba
,em htiw gnola ykrej fo kcits eht flah gniraet ,pu kool I
.ti raet ot gniog s’eh …eh ,hguor
.yawa raf osla si nisaB ,kcab gnikooL .ecnatsid eht nI
llah eht ssorca morf eciov retfos ,renniht a raeh I
.em ot ti gnireffo ,etteragic rehtona tuo gnillup
”retaW fo noitaerC ehT“   yojne esaelP
gnikael mih leef nac …I …I
,si yllaer eh gib woh llet t’nac I …I
eno siht piks esaelp
.slatem drah hguorht naelc tuc slennut gnilzzup fo krowten gnilwarps a
…raeb eht morf stfird ezag sih sa neve ton ,siht ta revaw neve t’nod stsurht siH
,derewol neeb ev’yeht erehw leef I litnu snaej sih pu meht ecart I
”.decneirepxeni elttil a s’eH“
.ti gnola ylkcils sedils dna sreyal eciov reh elihw
.gnol erofeb em gnola gnihsam ruf kciht dna htmraw hsulp
,ymrots dna krad ,ydoom ,wonk uoy
nepo tleb sih skrow  eh nehw ot desoppus ton  m’I raelc s’ti tub
,dnopser ot woh wonk
.seye ym revo trihs ym sehsam yldrawkwa dna ni spets eh sa
?haey ,yob s’ydal nosiuC taht …hu er’uoY“
.gnihtemos ta gnirats …m’I
.yob em llac osla mih gniraeh driew sleef ti
…nwod llewriats eht gnikat
.yob doog a er’uoY .hmM“  .mra ym gnibbur
won ssenkaew wohs I
,elzzum ym no yvaeh mih leef nac I tub
,emarf yrruf  ,yvaeh ,ybbuhc sih dna lla eh t neewteb  em rehtoms ot gniyrt s’eh ekil
.ecaf ym gnola gnisserp htgnel kcils ylthgils sih
,wap sih htiw ydaets em gnipeek s’eh ykcul s’eH
,llew sa raelc woleb yks eht sevael tI
,roolf tsrif eht no s’moor yM
,krad saw thgin eht tnaem yltsom tub
.mih otni bur yltneg sdnah ym sa
.bmalflow elttil suoicerp s’newG ekil ssel mees ot troffe na ni sehtolc lufroloc erom ym fo lla dehcneb ylteiuq ev’I
,no emoC“  -eman eht s’tahW
,ffuh elttil a evig I
,kcab tuc dluohs eh mih llet dna yrt ot htuom ym nepo
.nirg dna gurhs ylerem I
?ma I fi tahw ,nam revetahW“
.tnemtrapa s’xoN eht yb
ni yaw sih gniyrp s’eh tub
,liardraug eht hguorht ylsselmaes edils I
,teef ym no ydaetsnu m’I
,klawtac eht no tops ym dnif
”~traehteews kcab thgir eb ll’I
noitcif trohs laerrus gnitirw si dna ,tsiyasse na sa skrow ohw ,anueL yb
.stsurht wollahs ni gnikrow
.elzzum ym revo lla gnipeerc htmraw ,kciht
,selbmum raeb ehT ”…ti no …gnikrow
?erehps…oporT .hU
,syawhtap ecnanetniam eht otni ,nwod m’I tahT
,evaheb ot woh em gnihcaet s’eh ekil
.ma I sa dedlofdnilb neve
.sraey hsi4 tsap eht rof reh gnivig neeb ev’I rewsna emas eht neeb s’tI
,naom elbidua ylerab tsomla na sevig rentrap siH
.elytsefil gnitae-taem elohw ym htiw reh eracs ton ot sevil ruo ni naoJ ybab htiw tseb eb dluow ti thguoht newG erehw gniteeM ylimaF tnatropmI yreV eht fo ,gnignir llits yromem eht
.éfac eht fo renroc yzoc eht ni
”.sretirw eht osla tub
,seman laer on ,tcatnoc on ,srebmun oN
daeh ym ni sregnil elbmur repeed s’raeb ehT
,ria eht ni yvaeh sleef noitseuq ehT
raeb eht ot stroper eH
,ecaf dednilb ym revo detniap yldrazahpah era muc fo sepor kcihT
”!kcab eht morf wodahs a ekil kool uoy
.em no flesmih gnisopmi ,gib s’eH
.tneloiv-non yleritne si
,ydaets em gnidloh
.ti xaler …ydaetS“
,ria eht otni selbmurg raeb ehT
saw I taht ma I yrgna woh ro
,reidaets dna reidaets sworg ti sa erp evisarba tsomla
”.yrros ylbirreT .yob ,ekatsim yM“
.ydaetsnu llits m’I
revetahw ro das eb ot si tnetni eht kniht t’nod I dna egnarts dna esned os si cisum reh fo lla
,mih krow em gnikam
.kcab yaw ym dnif ot hguone railimaf s’ti ecno mih knaht I litnu
,elpuoc eht
.won oediv eht esuap ot evah I
,drawrof gnihcrul eb tsum eh sa daeh ym gnola gnihsam  fo dnik hcamots sih leef nac I
,rettib sih etsat em gnikam
.weiv ym dekcolb raeb eht erofeb
.gninrom eht ni gniht tsrif rewohs ot evah ll’I
.mih morf hgual ytraeh ,yvaeh a steg tI
,ti fo hsalf a tsuj ,niap s’erehT
.ereh redro gnikcep a fo tib a s’ereht ,yoB“
.emahs ot kcolb eritne eht tup ot gniyrt er’yeht ekil
.em rof enim sthgil eh sa mih morf nirg ykeehc rehtonA
,pleh elttil a deen I“ .tsehc ym no
I woh ro ,dnuora dehsup
,laer neve t’nsi taht retaw yllaicepse ,retaw tuoba yasse na ekam ot ynnuf s’tI“
”retaW fo noitaerC ehT“
?taeh eht si tsrif eht kniht I
.cinut neerg a ni yob flow elttil eht htiw eno eht …hu
,retsaf gnihtaerb m’I
?elbissop sa ytterp sa kool syawla retaw ekam ot ytud nmelos eht si ti taht naem taht seod oS“
,gnidnal eht leef neve t’nod I
.egdirf-inim a rof pu evas ot gniyrt ydaerla m’I dna
,pu trihs ym gniggut
.sthgil mid eht ni detum srehtaef neerg
”-wen s’eh ,no emoc hO“
.hu eht ,sduolc eht ni gnignah
,gniht eht no edalb tcnitsid a ees ot yaw on s’ereht taht tsaf os gnivom
.uoy revo epard ot gniht a ,yhport a
?nwod em gnikat eh si htap hcihW
”-sdnah sih barg ,yeh ,hnnN“
.enod tsomla er’uoy tub
”.tseb ym gniod m’I ,wonk uoy ,yeH“
?haey ,dnuos dna efas emoh uoy ekat ll’I dna ,no ti tuP“
.yawhtap rehtona nwod em sdael eh sa yawa kool dna yrt tsuj I
…yleugav s’regit eht plug ot dah I .gnilbmur
,mroftalp gnitaolf siht fo krowten gnilwarps eht no pu tliub
”.niaga htuom raluger a evah ot doog s’tI“
,kcoc s’regnarts rehto eht htiw tem m’I dna
.egdirf eht ni neeb s’ti
,tsew dna tsae raf eht gnola ni gnipeerc yradnuoB eht ees neve nac I
.taorht ym pu gnikohc s’gnihtemos ekil leef I
,won eno evah dluoc I …eerht …owT
,daeh ym ot kcab won
.rehguor elttil a gnitteg stsurht sih
,retaw fo ssalg a teg ot pu teg I
,nirg gums sih edih t’nac raeb ehT
”~yoB  ,llew os did uoY“
.gnikam saw ehs doof eht llems dluoc I
,resolc ni gnippets s’eh tub yltbus gnivom spih
,ylsselemahs trihs ym revo gnihsurb ,pu gnidilg
,su yb ssap ot hguone etanutrofnu duolc  yreve tsom
,noisserpxe ym ta rae ot rae morf gninnirg s’raeb ehT
…teg ot emit tseb eht saw ti taht dediced I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
?ereht sevlehS eht ni gnivil rehtorb a sah ymereJ kniht I
ecaf ym ni gninrub emahs fo hsur eht leef I ,ot evah I …I
,dnegel cisum loohcs dlo
,ekoms etteragic yb detniat llits si tnecs siH
…  …  ”.yob ,sruoy si eciohC“
,wollef naiva ehtil a nwod gnirats m’I
.ti seod ysaE“  .resolc s’eh
.redluohs ym gnivael t’nsi dnah sih tub
”.redrum htiw yawa teg uoy teb I
.regit sseltrihs ,nael a fo redluohs eht gnola depard dna pu si gel rieht
,yddaD ro riS …ekat ll’I
,em tsniaga gnitaidar taeh leef dna
,syadiloh gib rof pu deissug steg syawla ynoclab elttil riehT
,taeb etarebiled ,yvaeh a  ,stfihs cisum ehT
,daeh eht yb em sah eh tub
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ni ekat ot niarts a ,kciht s’eH
,uoy ees t’ndid tsomla I
.taorht ym fo kcab eht otni gnihsalps
.ti yb defrawd yliratnemom raeb eht fo tnecs rettib eht
,mih ni depolevne m’I ekil s’ti si eh gib revewoh dna
,ni skrow eh sa naorg hguor aa evig I
,ekil tfihs sih t’nsaw …tfihs siH
.sllab evissam sih revo  gnileef m’I
,ecno ta tih sgniht fo tol A  ”~spoO“
,em htiw tneitap s’eH
hhhhhS“   .ydob detniat sih ni detniat t’nsi taht htaerb a ekat t’nac I
,regnol tnemom a retfa edisa dellup fo dnik s’eH
.gniht dlihc detpoda elohw ym fo trap
.elttil a sessalg reh detsujda ehS
teiuq m’I .teiuq tsuj m’I
.gniliar eht no otni flesym dekrow dah I tonk eht morf em llup yltneg ot gnipleh
-gnipmuh dna gnipmuh  kcoc sih ,ydob sih ,ruf sih
.lliw ydaerla ebyam ehS
”…krad eht ni tihs ot pu teg
,retal ti hctawer ll’I
,ffffP“  .dees sih fo steluvir enecsbo ni tnorf ym gnitaoc
.ylhguor wollaws dna etib ym hguorht elbmum I ”.tey gnihton …hhU“
.em dniheb ni gnilttes erofeb tnemom a rof tsuj
taht sriatspu tuo dennalp ,desopmoc eht morf detarapes os
,nwod tser eht gnikrow otni lworg fo dnik I .tihS
.em ta gnikool osla saw ymereJ esuaceb ylbaborp
ta sesolc gnihtyreve ,tnelis ,ytpme
.hguoht stsurht wollahs gnivig si eH
,yrots a fo trap a gnieb fo nedrub eht ti htiw yrrac ot sah tI
,evisserppo ,kcihT
.emoh teg I nehw newG ot trihs gnissim a nialpxe ot evah I esle ro evac ot evah I
,ni sehsup  eh sa gnilbmurg
.erac reven dna shtap dna sllah knalb lortap ereh srekrow eht ,ylno noitcnuF
,elpuoc eht hcaorppa ot ylno
,gniht tneve rehtaew citamard a fo esac eht ni gnitacoler ycnegreme lanoisacco eht dna selag dna sduolc mrots driew fo sdnik lla ecaf attog s’adogaP ykS eht ,eb ot sah ti ,dilos tliub si ecalp siht dnA
,rentrap sih dnuora rediw gnidaerps tils rieht gniees
,gniracnu ,em otni gnidnirg
?nalp a tog uoY“
.gnillaf dna gnillaf ma I dna niar m’I .niar m’I tub
,ysae dna ecin si eciov siH
ereh morf kcolB eht otni teef ym kcik dluoc I ekil
lleh sa yecirp dna lanasitra s’tI .ecalp ruo morf renroc eht dnuora gnihtemos fo ecils a ot flesym taert ll’I yllanoisacco ,secils imalas ,seikrej ,staem kcans tsuj s’ti won oS
.pu siht revoc ot evah I ,on …I ,ti deyojne
tub ekoj eht edam yug eht nehw tuo denoz fo dnik I  ”.ylsuoivbo
,gnikcub ,pu gnipmar s’eH
…tsuj ,mrots a ton s’taht dniw teg ot doog sleef tI
.tuo gnimoc morf gnihtemos peek ot evah I
?siht yned I od …I
.tey doohrobhgien a yldrah
.setteragic fo gnikeer ,ykcits ,detniat
,repeed elttil a tsuj
.kaeb rieht gnimarf ,eye na gnirucsbo
,meht llems llits nac I hcum woh tuoba kniht ton ot gniyrt ,elbmum I
.niaga em htiw tespu eb ot gniog si idrataM .rM ?kniht I
,mih revo redduhs elatllet a s’ereht tub
.siht did yeht dna ,cinahcem a sa gnivid decudortni seires eht
.pu em gnitteg s’eH
.sregnif ym ni ylsuovren etteragic eht kcilf I
.era swap sih gib woh em gnittih s’tI
,repeed ni gnivird
.yldab os pu gnizeerf m’I
”-I“   .gnorts os s’eh …eH
.dnirg yreve htiw elttil a htuom ym ni borht yltneg mih leef nac I
,elttil a yb ylno tub
.yawa elim a em no ti llems lliw newG
.emityad si tfihs s’ymereJ yppah tsuj ma I
,doog kool retaw ekam ot tnatropmi syawla s’ti ,syawla
.rood kcab eht hguorht m’I emit eht yb esnes sekam gnihtoN  .eybdooG
,gnihtemos ro rotareneg a ot esolc ebyam er’eW
…peek ot evah I .siht ekil ton
,ssyba eht otni elgnad sgel yM
.dik wen rieht dna
,sthgis eht ees annaw uoy ,emoh og annaw t’nod uoy ,tsoL“ .si ti ebyaM
.rae eerf ym gnippin
.kcirp gnidavni sih fo edisrednu eht gnola  ylismulc eugnot ym daenk ot gnitrats otni
”.pu uoy teg s’tel
.esruoc fo ,niaga evom ot sah ti litnu ,sregnil ti erehw sduolc eht fo tuo eloh a gnihcnup
,sey tub ti tuoba etabed elpoep fo tol A
.ymereJ ot elims flah a evig I ”.oddik yeH“
.detcerid ecno dadpets ym lacisum a morf gnos a ot gnimmuh reh raeh nac I
.revo gniht elohw eht elppot dna
…  ”.suirauqA morf ffo syaw elttil a er’eW
…siht hguorht dnah a deen uoy fI .raey roineS
”?thgir ,flow enol a eb ot nosaer on s’ereht llew
”.enif eb annog er’uoy
.yadrutaS no gnippohS
.mih ot yvaeh gnulc ekoms etteragic fo llems eht dna ,yvaeh ,thgiewrevo s’eH
”~hguoht flesruoy naelc uoy gnihctaw ekil I“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
?daetsni taht yas
,yvaeh dna mraw si eciov siH
,tneced ,etilop tsuJ
.pmup hcir retfa pmup
-sffilc rebma owt eht neewteb degdew ,gib
,ecaf s’rentrap sih gnola ylevissessop gnihsup si wap siH
.ekoj elttil reh htiw desaelp ,gnilims s’ehS
”~ytterp os si ruf ruoy ,kcuF
,srenroc eht tuo ylissem loord dna htuom ym llif ti  gnivah
,tnarbiv dna kciht skool retaw ehT
.ereh gnivah reve s’eno on ytrap eht ot etal sruoh 2 m’I .mp9 …ekil
,regae  era stsurht siH
.uoy ni s’tahw no
,ni skrow eh sa ecalp ni  em  gnipeek swap
”.stnerap ynam oot evah ydaerla I“  ”.kcip ruoy
,nisaB evoba gnignah yltnatsnoc
,noisnet ym seciton eH
.hguoht sraews eh woh ekil t’ndluow newG
.nwod em gnihsup ,ecaf ym no tub
,eciton tuohtiw dnuorgkcab eht otni sdnelb muh tnatsnoc eht
”.sredle ruoy ot netsil attog uoy ,wen er’uoY
.ti revo flesym epard dna liardraug eht fo trap gnigguh
,em swonk yug siht fi neve
.rehtom doog ,laer a dah ecno I ekiL
,yllanif ti revo lla dees fo sraems dna sepor kciht eht gniees ,ylkaew gnitnap m’I
.llits gnirekcins
”.detacilpmoc yllaer sdnuos tI“
.enola ton er’ew taht eb tsuj dluoc ti tub
.kcab eciov ym teg ot hguone wollaws ot gniyrt ,don I tub
,evil I erehw swonk eh fi
,htuom ym morf gnizoo ylwols si ssenrettiB
.tneduts etirovaf sih m’I gnikniht otni flesym deloof ev’I ro
.amrif arret no ni gnimooz ylsselmaes ,yltneg …resolc
,tsol yrev m’I ”-tsol ton m’I“
…hmM“  .ruf ym otni gnignilc
.yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I …I
”-enod m’I litnu niaga pu denaelc gnitteg t’nia uoY“
fo enil ykcits a gnileef ,htaerb etarepsed a hctac I
c …tsuj I dna gnits eson ym ekam ot hguone etsat eht
,ylhguor nwod plug a ekohc I
,sey srengised eht ot smelborp fo tsen xelpmoc a eb nac ti gnitplucs yllatigid fo tca eht tub
m‘ ,fH“  ”~kcab tuc dluohs uoy uoy dloT“
.erom dna erom no elip ot sreward ym morf sehtolc naelc ydaerla emos gnillup
.ecaf ym gnola pu
.rehtegot gnignilc lla tekcaj  dna ruf dna trihs ym
.revetahw ro ,em tuoba erom nrael ot ti ta gnikool ton ylraelc s’eH
.tekcaj kcalb ym no gnillup ,kcab eht tuo pils I
niaga hcrul ot trats I litnu ni gnihsup
.gnivom erofeb em revo gnittep wap eerf sih
.gnippohs litnu yad a eno ot nwod eb d’I neht tub
.peelsa s’gel ym kcuF .kcuF
.ti s’taht dnA .yob doog A
.ees t’nac I taht foorp detsefinam
loohcs hgih gnitrats ecnis revE
,gnitacorpicer otni em gnisae  ,ylthgil  gnipmuh
,ylevissessop daeh ym no erew swap rellams siH
.liocer I sa nwod em gnihsup
,nam a s’eh skniht dik A
-nrocirpaC ,4 levelbus