eno siht piks esaelp
hguohtla ,sdnuorg ytisrevinu eht ssorca tuo gnikool
.htob meht detius tahw dnif ot tsuj ,kcoc s’retxaB dnuora tnuoma llams a gnitator
.mih ot tsael ta ,flesti evol saw retxaB
ot doog tlef llits ti tub – ylpmis erom desaelp eb dluoc taht tfahs a ton saw tI .kcoc sih gnikorts ni yksuh eht dediug yltneg dna deddon melaS
tnereffid yrev neeb evah dluoc sgnihT   .taht rof reippah eb dluoc rehtien dna
,detalucaje eh sa mih rof hcum oot ylpmis eloh liat s’ynnub eht fo llup dna hcnelc
.od ot elbissop saw tlef eh sa mih no noitnetta hcum sa gnihsival ,nwod dna pu daeh sih debbob melaS
ot tsehc s’yksuh eht fo esir gniredduhs eht morF
eraM tsyhtemA yb
,mih hguorht desruoc tsul elihw
,ylippah demmuh yksuh ehT
wolloh ,supmac eht ssorca deohce hgual A
.gniggaw liat sih ,sdrow htiw delggurts retxaB teY   ”…evah dluohs I
.tsael yrev eht ta ,deruovas eb ot saw tI
,tfahs s’retxaB fo htgnel eht nwod dna pu dils elzzum siH
.revewoh ,retxaB htiw eb ot detnaw eh fi erus t’nsaw eH
.og tel ot detnaw niaga reven eh fi sa deknilretni sregnif rieht
,ylivaeh detnap eH
neve…leef ot tnaw I tuB .doog os sleef htuom ruoY
.meht rof drah yllaer
”?evael ot evah ew
.htgnel s’retxaB no nwod tas ylwols eh sa sgniht koot eh ylkciuq woh tsuj melaS ot pu lla saw ti ,ereht morF
.ylticilpxe detats lla ti evah ot gnideen tuohtiw
.yksuh eht ecaf ot denrut eh sa lohocla eht emalb t’ndluoc eh os ,knird ot gnihtyna dah t’ndah melaS   .ti did eh
sgel sih koot ti hguoht ,spih s’yksuh eht gnilddarts ynnub eht ,dessik yehT
gnitfil liat llams sih
.niaga meht neewteb ecaps tup ot
ereh gniyats uoy era ,oS“
etuc“ a gnikam ,rehtegot erew yeht demussa srehto rof ,setad neeb evah llew sa yam taht sgnituo neeb neve d’erehT .sterces rieht lla gnillips ,pu gnittis ,yksuh eht dna mih neewteb gniklat sthgin etal ynam os neeb d’erehT .thguoht d’eh sa
.esaelp ot mih rof elgna retteb a ta saw ti os ,elttil a pu kcoc s’god eht gnidloh dna edisni ti gnilkcus
saw tI .htrof dna kcab gnidils
.wap sih otni yltnapmar gnitsurht ,yrc a tuo tel
,egelloc fo tuo hserf ton dna tneduts erutam a sa gnidnetta saw eh yhw snosaer eht fo eno
,rehtona eno tsniaga depmub llits skcoc rieht
.saw ti elbatrofmoc woh dekil melaS dna
,elbatrofmoc saw melaS hguoht nevE
,meht neewteb yllufituaeb gnilkcarc
.lla ti ksir dna dniw eht ot lla ti worht ot ,yug fo dnik taht t’nsaw eH .enasni
,taht ekil esolc dellup ylirgnuh dna dleh eb ot detnaw eH
.noitacol lacisyhp ni tsael ta
,yltniaf ni gniggid ,sregnif s’yksuh eht ot etib etarepsed a saw erehT
.retal stnemom wef a ylno ffo tibbar eht thguorb
seert suorefinoc ehT
hguoht ,pleh elttil a tuohtiw ton ,noitartenep rof hguone drah teg netfo t’ndid tI
.hcum taht lla tibbar eht rehtob t’ndid taht
.retpahc txen eht ni
,no gniog saw tahw noitseuq ot dah neve reven eh taht mih rof ylpeed os
.ti fo ekas eht rof xes gnivah tuoba gniog tsuj t’nsaw eh taht ,thgir saw
”?I t’nevah ,hguoht yrt ot toG …suovren m’I
.ti ni rehtegotla tnetop erom gnihtemos dah shtuom rieht neewteb derahs yeht ria yrev eht fi sa ,ecalp otni ,ylsselhtaerb
.rehtegot resolc meht gnirb ylno dluow ti tub ,esac taht ni ,gnikcip fo egrahc ekat ot tuoba saw eninac eht gniht doog a saw tI   ”?ew naC
,tonk s’god eht saw tahT
pleh yna deen uoy oD“ .dias tibbar eht
.elyts wen a tuo gniyrt saw eh woh
.eslup tuoved retfa eslup
.erusaelp rieht gnikat dna
,neht neve ,tnereffid eb ot evah ton did
.od dluow melaS dna retxaB tahw yltcaxe saw taht ,rehtegoT
,revewoh ,tniop eht ton saw dees sih fo tnuoma ehT
d’yehT .setunim ro sdnoces rof rehtehw erus ton
?spetswap sih dessim eh dah woh
– dnuora yaw eht lla sregnif sih esolc t’ndluoc eh erehw ezis a fo saw tI
.flesmih pots dluoc eh erofeb dehgual tibbar ehT
mriuqs ton did yksuh eht teY
”.ti rof ydaer yllautca ton er’ew ekiL
snoitcerid riehT .skeew fo elpuoc a yb tsuj ,ereht yats noitadommocca s’melaS dnetxe ot yaw a dnuof yeht fi neve
taht ekil esle enoemos tsniaga spih sih llor dna hsup ot egnarts saw tI
.taht flesmih yned t’ndluow eh dna
.eye sih ni tnilg ykeehc a
sih hguoht ,sdrow dnif ot deirt melaS   ”…I …retxaB“
.evom erad t’ndid ynnub eht tey ,esolc os
.yltnasaelp nups daeh sih sa s’yksuh eht tfel ylerab spil
,nesohc d’eh tops eht dna supmac eht tuohguorht level ton saw dnuorg ehT
.ti rof gnihca ,erom gnitnaw
.mih ot rumrum s’retxaB gnihctac
,lla retfa ,s’yksuh eht naht retrohs saw elzzum
,nihc s’retxaB woleb pu depporp nihc sih ,tsehc s’yksuh eht no despalloc dna nwod emac eh litnU
.reteiuq hcum ydaerla erew sgniht
,ti gnibmuht ,daeh eht revo wap s’yksuh eht fo hsurb eht nevE
.wap s’yksuh eht otni gnitsurht ynnub eht
.taht ekil tnemom a ni ton dluoc seidob rieht taht
.lla ta mih draeh neve yksuh eht rednow a saw ti ylteiuq os ,denaorg melaS
,meht neewteb ssenesolc lacisyhp taht dah yeht nehw retteb saw tI   .gnidnuop traeh
.taht naht ssel on dna erom on
,ylteews rehtegot emac gnihtyreve taht htob meht rof thgir taht ylpmis saw tnemom eht ebyam rO
,mih edisni llits saw kcoc s’god ehT
.gnihctiwt srae ,delahxe melaS
.gnivaeh tsehc s’melaS ,flesmih eninac a saw eh ekil ylivaeh erom gnitnap
,yltaen dettols gnihtyreve neht dnA
.revo lla gnirevihs ,hcuot s’eninac eht otni denael dna denaom melaS
,meht neewteb dna srae s’tibbar eht nwod dehtooms sregnif s’retxaB
.eerged sih fo raey tsal eht revo mih otni dellird neeb ton dah ti fi sa ton saw ti
,ydob s’yksuh eht fo htgnel eht pu detniuqs melaS   ”?hpmM“
,wap sih ni ti dezeeuqs ,revewoh ,retxaB
.thgin taht nwonk sgnileef rieht edam t’ndah yeht fi
rieht ,rehtona eno detsat yeht sa s’yksuh eht tsniaga detrap spil siH
.tseb eht tlef taht ,pit eht sdrawot pu kcab gnisserp ekil
,mih no erew seye s’god eht wonk ot ton saw melaS hguoht ,noitisop a hcus ni gnihtyna wohs yllaer ot llams oot saw liat s’ynnub A
dael eht ekat tibbar eht gnittel yksuh eht ,efil ni egats rieht ta ,taht naht erom gnihton dedeen yehT
gnihtyreve erus ekam ot detnaw d’eh teY
tsomla mih dessik eninac ehT
,seye sih otni derats ynnub eht sa oot htaerb sih gnidloh eb ot demees dna yawa
”,uoy rof tseb s’revetahw
,nwod yaw eht lla gnidils srexob sih
,hcum noitnetta eud diap neeb evah dluohs taht noitcennoc eht dna
.htrig sih dnuora nepo dehcterts
,ylthgil derepmihw eh dna mih hguorht dehca
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ecalp ni gnirevihs ,drawrof dexif seye sih tpek llits tibbar eht hguoht
,keehc s’yksuh eht puc ot ssendlob eht dnif ot deganam melaS ,noitcerid rehto eht sdaeh rieht gnitliT
.ylthgil gnitnurg
,oot seye esoht ni regnuh a saw erehT
ylthgil delims eH
,yksuh eht morf ecnatsid a ta hctorc nwo sih tup ti fi neve ,nwod dils eh ,oS
,sehcni ruof ta mih rof hguone egral saw ti tub ,tfahs sih fo esab eht dnuora htaehs a evah ton dluoc eH
.dias dah stnerap sih os ro – gnikniht fo yaw driew a dah eH .delims melaS
er’erehT .ykcul teg ll’I ebyam tub
,no evom ot emit saw tI
.egnahc gib a s’tI .tol a s’tI
,yako eb ot gniog s’tI“
.ebul eht etipsed emit sih gnikat
lla ta ton saw melaS hguoht
,mih dnuora dewollaws eh dna
?t’nsaw ti fi tahw dnA
shturt hserf gnirevocnu ,ti otni evled dna neeb dah tahw
.esimorp fo lluf eno saw taht ekil
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.riah pu deffulf ,trohs sih hguorht dekaerts eulb fo tnih a
,wap sih gnipsalc ,detnap retxaB
.neht neve ton ,ti fo laed gib a ekam ot tnaw t’ndid eH .ecnacifingis laer yna fo gnihtyna ton ,tnemmoc gnissap
,mih dnuora pu emac swap s’retxaB
erofeb ,gnihtyreve ees ot detnaw tsuj I ,haeY“
.elbatrofmoc teg ot gniyrt
,hO …hA“   .seitiliba rieht fo tseb eht ot seidob s’rehto hcae yojne dna erolpxe ot ereht erew yeht nehw ton ,hsur a eb ot evah t’ndid erehT
yeht gnihtemos ot rood a gninepo
,woleb edam neeb dah sllab llams fo riap A
.rehtegot ,retpahc txen rieht saw tI
,llitS .loohcs ni kcab yaw melaS detaert srehto woh rof dias eb dluoc naht erom tol a
,yltnasaelp yrev ,saw ssa sih sa
ton dluoc melaS hguoht ,teiuq eht ekorb retxaB   ”?tib a rof
eveihca ot yaw eno saw tI
,sucof ot od dluoc melaS lla saw tI
rehto hcae otni xaler dluoc yeht ,erehT
.elbat edisdeb eht fo reward eht morf ebul eht tuo hsif ot retxaB detcerid eh sa niaga spih s’yksuh eht revo tlenk tibbar ehT
ohw enoemos tub ,renroc sih ni enoemos gnivah naht eroM .taht detnaw eH .taht dedeen eH   .ti rof ksa ot gnivah neve tuohtiw dedeen d’eh tahw tsuj ,yllacisnirtni ,nwonk dah eninac eht fi sa ,mih ot tol a tnaem dah edis sih no yksuh eht gnivah
yhw saw taht ebyaM
”…mmM“   .eroc sih ta gniloop tsul htiw drawrof gnidnirg
,edir eht yojne ot
.mih hguorht llor ti gnittel ,dehtuom-nepo denaorg eh dna
ssik a tub ,ssik fo tros ysmulc a saw tI .rehto hcae tsniaga pu gnipeews
redisnoc ot detnaw eh tuB
,resolc mih ward ot
seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,uluL
,mih ta kool ot gninrut ,dias yksuh eht
,ylthgils kcab llup ot ssik eht gnikaerb ,denaorg yksuh ehT
,demmurht meht neewteb ycamitni dna ssenesolc eht sa ton
,kcoc s’god eht dnuora sregnif sih dah ynnub eht hguoht ,spil sih gnikcil ,ylthgil denaom eH
,daeha saw tahw fo kniht ot deen t’ndid eH .mih detius tahT
”.krow gnihtemos ekam ll’eW
,eman sih dehtaerb yksuh ehT   ”?melaS“
,shtuom rieht edisni gnilruc dna gnikcilf seugnot
.rentrap sih otni muc fo strups toh ,gnol gnidnes dna lortnoc gnisol
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
.rehtie tuoba yrrow ot )!gnisirprus neeb evah dluow
.rehto hcae gnisserdnu ,ylkciuq oot ,dna sehtolc s’rehtona eno htiw gnilbmuf
.sgel s’retxaB neewteb kcab gnihctiwt llits dna pu delruc
.egnahc dluow gnihtyreve dna retxaB ot sdrow elttil os ton eerht esoht yas d’eh ,yad enO
,syaw etarapes rieht gniog erew yehT
,tamrof driew a ni VC ym tup ot em dlot yehT
”.ot dnim ruoy tes uoy revetahw od syawla uoY .ti wonk tsuj I
,yltneg daeh s’melaS denrut eh sa spil sih ta dehctiwt elims A
”retpahC txeN ehT“
.wam sih morf gnillips eugnot knip fo htgnel elbixelf a
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.hcuot regae s’melaS otni debborht dna s’ynnub eht naht regral saw tfahs sih teY
.odnecserc lufituaeb a ot gnimoc erusaelp
”,taht tuoba kniht t’nod
.taht ssim ot gniog saw eH
nellaf dah thgiN
dna ylivaeh dort yksuh ehT
,revewoh ,noitcartta leef ot flesmih gnidnatsrednu koot tI
.ecnahc rieht dessim d’yeht ,taht ekil gnihtyna rof etal oot saw tI .ti od t’ndluoc
,denepeed ssik eht ,thgin eht fo daed eht ni meht dnuora esle gnihton htiW
hguoht ,taht ekil gnihtemos ro
gniod eb ot desoppus saw eh saw ti tahw wonk t’ndid tsuj eH
lla ta tlef retxaB fi wonk neve t’ndid eh dnA
.weiv morf supmac eht fo strap rewen eht dekcolb
ylidaeh gnitnurg
.eloh liat s’melaS fo tuo ti gnipeek ,ti dnuora gnihcnip sregnif sih
.htap sih ni digir oot eb ot tnaw t’ndid melaS ,edis taht nO .lacirotsih
.enot sih ni ecilam on ,llat gnidnats srae s’tibbar kcalb eht ,delims melaS
,skriuq rieht lla htiw sgnidliub dlo eht ni ,ytisrevinu eht ta gniyduts emit rieht gnirud esolc neeb d’yehT
,snoitca niatrec erew ereht dna evitisnes tsom eht saw daeh ehT .tsethgils eht ni gniht dab a saw taht fi sa ton
.tsethgils eht ni
tliub yletaredom eht ,esruoc fo ,retxaB sediseB
,talf llams s’melaS ot kcab yaw rieht delbmuts yeht ,wap ni waP
,raf os ,meht neewteb saw taht lla nehw yllaicepsE
,esolc erew yehT
.ecno ta lla mih hguorht llor hcum oot tel ot ton gniyrt
– degrogne deniamer tonk eht tey
,htuom sih ni yug rehtona fo trap tserednet eht gnidloh ,ti tuoba lautcnitsni ylpmis gnihtemos saw erehT .oot
,teiuq yliree tfel saw supmac eht dna
”…heh ,htaehs a evah d’uoy togrof I“
.tseretni fo dnik taht evah t’ndid tsuj
dna drawrof gniog taht fo
neve erew erehT .mih rof drah saw tcatnoc eye degnolorp hguoht neve
.reffo ot dah retxaB tahw ees ot detnaw yllaer eh
”?taht htiw pu s’tahW …mH“
.skeehc sih morf gnisir hsulb a fo taeh eht ,delggig melaS dna tem seye riehT
”,yako s’ti ,yako s’tI“
.ti ot yenruoj eht tub
.ytisrevinu eht ta
,mih ot resolc ni detfihs melaS dna demriuqs eH
,denaom retxaB ”,haey ,hO“
.dnuof eh tahw yb desirprus elttil a ,derumrum eh ”,hO …mmM“
”,ti ekam ll’uoy wonk I“
.raey a revo ni enoyna htiw neeb t’ndah tsuj eh rof ,ecneirepxeni yllacinhcet ton ,lleW
tub – erofeb sserdnu fo segats suoirav ni rehto hcae nees d’yehT
?tuo dnats d’ti diaS …repap knip no
.ylthgil deborp retxaB
.oga sraey ytriht…ytnewt
.ydob s’eninac eht morf htmraw fo hcuot a gnilaets
– sgniht koot yeht erehw ,did yeht tahw ,degnahc sgniht woh tsuj meht ot pu lla saw tI
.doog dekool ti thguoht llits
,tey od ot tnaw I tahw wonk
sa taews htiw pmad ylthgil tsehc sih ,detrap spil ,sdrow yna tuo teg t’ndluoc eH
,sseldrager ereht demool dah ti ,seiduts sih dna eerged sih no gnisucof neeb evah dluohs eh hguoht nevE
.selkna s’tibbar eht dnuora gniloop ydaerla snaej
.rehtie taht dnim t’ndid retxaB demees ti dna
.gnihctiwt liat sih ,ylthgil detnap eh dna no mih degaruocne eninac eht morf naorg A   .ylteews dna yltfos
?gnihtyreve retfa ,meht od taht dluow doog tahW
.ti htiw elbatrofmoc saw melaS hguoht
.yltnevref erom rehtegot kcab spil rieht hsurc ot ylno ,gnitnap ,ssik eht ekorb yehT
,oot ereht ni nworb dna neerg fo skcelf
.ylnmelos gnirewot sgnidliub enots ,dlo eht
.ynnub eht ot txen llaw eht ot no yllausac pu gnippoh ,elims a htiw dias retxaB
ylkciuq oot mih tfel sdrow ehT   ”.t’nod I ,oN“
daeha hcum os saw erehT
,gnisaet dna gnihctarcs
”.uoy fo erom
.ssik eht otni naorg delffum a tuo gnittel
taht( cilbup ni no-drah a gnitteg fo nrecnoc eht evah t’ndid
”.daeha sgniht gniticxe evah ylno ll’uoy wonk I .ti od ot tog ev’ew tuB
.ereht snoitalever rehtruf gnirb dluow sruoh thgilyad dna gninrom eht tub
eb dluow erehT .taht rof emit rehtonA   .thgin taht tibbar eht otni gniknis eb ton dluow ti hguohtla
.ylmraw ,yltnasaelp gninruhc hcamots sih ,taeb a deppiks traeh sih woh erongi ot deirt eH
gnitrats dna remmuS ylrae ni gnidne ,sretsemes raluger eht gnirud gniyduts esoht rof tsael ta
.spil sih gnikcil ,detnurg yksuh eht
.tnemom elgnis yreve desiromem eh os ,gnihtyreve ni ekat ot detnaw eH
,ylthgils htrof dna kcab elzzum sih denrut dna yksuh eht dnuora denaorg eH
,no erew spmalteerts eht dna
,ruf yerg ,tfos sih ni gnikat ,yksuh eht ot denrut eh sa oot ti wenk melaS dna tuo gninnur saw emit teY
.erac t’ndid ynnub eht hguohtla ,ehcysp sih fo trap lanrac
,emit tsrif eht hcterts a fo hcum oot neeb evah dluow tI
ytinutroppo elpma retxaB gnivig ,ylwols yrev
segassap sih htob htiw gnihcnelc
,saw ti tahw rof tnemom eht deyojne eh tub
.rehtegot tif ot tnaem erew yeht fi sa saw tI
,stnemom gnol wef a rof ecnelis elbanoinapmoc ni ereht tas yehT
.sknaht ,pleh eht evol d’I ,haeY“
.ynapmoc meht peek ot ytic emitthgin teiuq eht dna edistuo teerts eht fo sdnuos eht ylno
,tnemom a roF   .gnihctiwt dna
.tuoba rehtona eno htiw hguone raelc neeb t’ndah
.gniog meht tpek taht meht neewteb
kool ot dah melaS .ynam taht lla ton tub
.tsrif seog dleif ym ni
.retxaB gniruovas ,ereht flesmih tsol dna ti rof detsul eH .esruoc fo ,ti htrow saw niarts ehT
,retxaB rof tiaw ot mih rof ,dne eht ni ,ti htrow neeb dah tI
tfel ydaerla dah stneduts eht fo tsom ,thgin ta etal oS
.hguorht emoc lla dah taht dalg saw eh dna
.mih htiw llew dehsem etiuq ton dah
,eb ot ti dedeen yeht lla saw tnemom eht tey
.detnaw eh sa tuo sdrow sih lla teg ot hguone ylraelc gnikniht t’nsaw yksuh ehT
saw hcihw ,ytisrevinu gnidnetta erofeb yregrus mottob enogrednu
llaw eht ffo mih llup ot
eh dnA .yssem elttil a eb dluoc ti
”?syad eseht latigid si ffuts taht lla wonk yeht t’noD
,hO .enips sih nwod gnikips llihc a
.daeha ylgnitnuad
.ruf rieht rof tub ,edun yltcefrep meht fo htob gnivael
saw melaS teY   .mih yb enif saw taht dna dnuora yna ylerab erew erehT
,eloh liat sih pu ebul melaS pleh ot yksuh eht rof stnemom wef a koot ylno tI
,dekrow evah dluow ti ebyaM“ .derettum eh
.hctorc sih sdrawot nwod gnidils sregnif
.ereh uoy gniees ycnaF“
.denaom yksuh ehT ”…melaS ,hA
…s’teL …uoy knahT“
,ereht kraps a saw erehT
ro tsal dluow sgnivas sih gnol woh erus
,ti ot pu emac eh nehw eugnot sih ffo decnuob tsomla ,derepat ,pit ehT
,hhhhO“   .dluoc eh sa htuom sih otni peed sa ti gnilkcus dna tfahs sih dnuora rediw spil sih gnihcterts
.morf emoc dah ti erehw tsuj llet t’ndluoc melaS hguoht ,gniohce dna
.yaw eht lla ton
eh rof ,lauxesa saw eh fi derednow neve dah yltsenoh eh
,taht naht erom yna eb ot deen t’nseod tI .hcuot ni yats
dna kcils dna mraw saw tI
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.emit taht ,eloh liat sih edistuo yllufknaht
a sa ffo ti yalp ot deirt melaS dna mih ot no dekcol noitnetta s’eninac ehT
aiv skoob dehsilbup-fles sah dna ,snoissimmoc sekat ohw
.erom neve gniworg saw tonk s’eninac eht hguoht neve
,nwod yaw eht lla knas eh sa pil rewol sih revo tuo desserp eugnot siH
.spil s’ynnub eht gnilkcit htaerb
,elihw elttil a rof yb teg ot ekat dluoc eh boj a htiw pu dne d’eh ,mih rof ylekil yltsoM
”,em htiw emoc ,esaelP“
,seitnewt etal sih ni
.tfahs drah-flah a gnieerf ,raewrednu sih fo tuo tibbar eht depleh eh sa derepmihw yksuh ehT   ”…no emoC“
,meht rof tsael ta ,hguorht emac lla tI
”.won tnereffid os s’tI
.yawa devom rehtien dna ,esolc oot
,htuom sih otni denaorg ynnub eht dna melaS naht tliub yldaorb erom saw retxaB
.mih yllub ot deirt dah puorg a nehw neve mih yb doots dah retxaB
oga emit gnol a enod evah dluohs spahrep eh tahw did eH .ti did melaS ,oS
,lla ta deneppah ton dah ti fi sa
.ot timda ot gnilliw ,raf os ,saw ynnub eht naht erom tnaem tI
.ti evol I ,gnizama s’tahT“
.noitisop a hcus ni saw eh nehw elzzum s’eninac eht ees ot mih rof tluciffid saw ti hguohtla
derac
sdnuorg ytisrevinu eht fo strap gnitanimulli
.ecap eht gnidiug ,dekil eh sa hcum sa
htgnel gnislup eht gnissik ,kcoc sih revo dna ydob s’yksuh eht nwod htap a deliart spil siH
”,noh ,doog sleef tahw em lleT“
demees tsuj htuos eninac eht wollof ot tub
”.revetahw ro boj miretni na rof elttes I erofeB
.emas eht lla god eht fo ssenesolc eht deyojne hguoht ,decniw melaS
.ssenkrad otni tsac llits erew saera emos elihw
.seye sih esolc ot raeb t’ndluoc eh hguoht ,gnisir deen ,kcab srae sih dedlof dna detnurg tibbar ehT
.eson gnihctiwt s’ynnub eht gnilkcit spil
.mih fo hcni yreve gniruovas ,tfahs s’eninac eht fo edisrednu eht ot pu ylgnisaet desserp eugnot s’melaS dna emit fo ytnelp
,eraM tsyhtemA yb ”retpahC txeN ehT“ saw sihT
.saw eh naht regnuoy saw eh taht noisserpmi eht evag erugif thgils ,thgil sih hguoht
.elttil a retxaB erolpxe dluoc eh os ssik eht gnikaerb ,derettulf sdileye s’melaS
melaS dna hcum oot saw saera fo evitisnes tsom sih no erusserp ehT
spih sih dekcor dna derepmihw yksuh ehT
,wap sih ni tfahs rellams s’melaS koot eh sa eldi eb ot deen t’ndid retxaB teY
”,renoos gnihtemos dias d’I hsiw I …retxaB …hA“
.nwo s’yksuh eht tsniaga ssik yhtaerb
,ti yas t’ndluoc eH .taht od t’ndluoc eh ,on ,hO …on
,dekcilf liat sih woh
.rood eht hguorht dna ni gnitteg no ylno tnetni
.selzzum s’rehtona eno gnirolpxe yldiugnal dna ylpeed gnissik
?gnihtemos od ot tegrof uoy diD“
.enim ot kcaB“ .dias melaS
naht erom gnihtyna rof htiw nrob neeb d’eh xes eht fo kniht ton did eh elihw
,ylwols gninetfos
,sredluohs sih fo llor eht morf desae noisnet dna eb ot dedeen eh erehw saw tI
,ffo raewrednu sih tog eh erofeb yksuh eht desuap melaS   ”…wonk uoY …I“
.mra sih ot gnulc rehto eht elihw
.tneduts a rof hguone naht erom saw ti fi neve
.sdrow sih revo gnihsur ,dias retxaB
,raey fo emit siht ta setaudarg rof gnikool secalp emos
,saw ti dnuora kciht woh htiw
…doog sleef taht ,ho
,hA“   .emit nevig yna ta od ot detnaw eh tahw kcip ot drah saw ti tub
,fles eurt sih gnirevocnu erofeb tuB .seipareht enomroh tnereffid revo dereffid
.elbbow elims sih tel ot ton deirt tub
od ot sih saw ydob siH
yllautca gnihtemos rof gnihcraes boj woh ees ot tnaw I os
.mih detavitpac taht kcoc fo htgnel htooms eht saw ti tey
,s’yksuh eht morf yawa kcoc sih llup ot saw ti sa drah sA
.kcen s’tibbar eht ta gnilbbin dna gnippin
,eraM tsyhtemA yb
gnihcaorppa eninac eht ot no thguac ton dah eh
.emit eht lla thgis nialp ni neeb dah taht
.ot elba eb ot gniog reve saw eh dias dah ynam naht rehtruf tol a emoc
.elddim sih dnuora ssentfos a htiw yksuh
.sloop eulb eht ni gniknird
.llits detrap ylthgils erew spil sih hguoht neve emit taht ssik etsahc a ,niaga mih dessik melaS
,mih dexaoc retxaB ”,melaS …esaelp
,dellif gnieb sllah noitadommocca tneduts eht fo yad tsal eht saw tI
.dewohs ecneirepxeni sih taht ,tnemom a rof ,deirrow eh dna
”?esaelP ?em htiw deb eht no pu emoc uoy nac
”,suolucidir s’taht ,haeY“
,ylrednet erom dessik yehT
saw ti ,oot nwod dna pu debbur ti evah
.aiglatson naht rehto ,ytisrevinu eht dnuora yats ot mih rof nosaer on saw ereht ,tibbar eht rof ,dna etaudarg a
,ydob sih revo swap sih gninnur retxaB htiw ,etunim gnissap yreve htiw os ylgnisaercni
.s’yksuh eht tsniaga tfahs drah-imes sih gnidnirg ,yltoh delahxe melaS dna
,lworg ynit a tuo tel dna detnurg retxaB sa kcab yksuh eht dna ynnub eht dloh ot gnihton saw erehT
stnerap sih hguohtla ,ytisrevinu nrehtroN eht ta srehto htiw llew gnola tog dah ynnub ehT
.trap rehto yna naht evitisnes erom daeh eht
.kcen sih fo kcab eht gnibbur dna gnitfihs ,delkcuhc retxaB
,ylsuoires ,yako s’tI“
…yako s’ti ,won ereh er’eW“
,erom gnihtemos htiw delgnat ,tsul fo ssenidaeh eht saw tI
.semitemos htgnel ym no thgit tib a steg fo dnik tI …haeY“
.meht dnuora daerps ot erom elttil a
mih etsat ot detnaw eh ,oot kcoc s’god eht no wap sih desu d’eh elihw gnidnirg neeb dah yeht erehw
dellortnoc eb ot ton saw spih sih fo krej ehT
mih rof tfel gnihton saw ereht teY
,elzzum trohs sih fo edis eht no mih ssik dluoc eh os hguone ylno
”.thgir s’taht ,peY“
,daeh sih morf daeh s’tibbar eht gnisiar yltneg
htuos nwod kcab gnidaeh eb ot desoppus saw retxaB
saw hcihw ,hcum taht lla ot emoc t’ndah ti ,syad esoht seitisrevinu ta erew sgniht woh htiw ,yllufknahT
sa rehtie eldi ton erew swap s’yksuh eht teY
”retpahC txeN ehT“
.tnemom eht liops ot gnitnaw ton ,ylteiuq dias melaS ”,os kniht I“
.erom neve yksuh eht otni sserp ot tnaw melaS edam
,eerged s’retsam a otni no gnivom t’nsaw eh dna oga htnom a dnuora eerged etaudargrednu sih morf detaudarg d’eH
.edisni peed dehca deen sih sa spih nwo sih gnikcor ,spil sih gnikcil ,tnemom eht revo gnitsul ,ereht regnil dluoc eh tuB
.muc-erp gnilbbird kcoc s’yksuh eht
”…heH“   ”.doog taht lla saw ereh gniht sreerac eht kniht t’nod I ?gniraperp
.noitnetta gniggeb rekcup thgit eht
.lla ta eciov sih gnisiar yldrah ,derepsihw eh
.ria thgin eht hguorht gniohce dnuos prahs eht ,dekrab retxaB ”!haeY“
,deneffits kcab sih dna dekcirp srae s’tibbar ehT   ”.ereh
,doog sa tsuj saw ti tub ,esruoc fo
,dekil eh taht osla msagro
.krow laer otni pets tsrif sih dnif ot elba eb ot gniog saw eh yltfiws woh
,wap s’eninac eht dezeeuqs eh sa ton ,derahs eb ot dedeen sdrow oN
,delbmarcs dna dehgual yeht ,wohemos ,sriats eht pu gnilbmuT
.yawa mih hsup ot tnaw t’ndid eh
,tfahs s’yksuh eht ot no nwod gnidnirg ,yltnegru erom spih sih dekcor tibbar ehT
.driew smees tI …siht lla retfa ffo gninnuR .ykcuL“
.tey dediced etiuq t’ndah yksuh eht
.pihsdneirf a saw
”.uoy rof gnihtyna od d’I“
noitiurf ot emoc etiuq ton
,esor dna esor deen sih sa mih hctac ot ereht saw retxaB teY
.dneirf ruoy s’eh dalg eB
nwod dekool ,llaw a no pu
,ydaerla pu tes sweivretni boj owt tog I“
.derettam esle gnihton fi sa gnidnirg dna gnitsurht ,ydob sih fo lliw eht dewollof eh dna ,pot no ynnub eht htiw ,noitom lanrac a hcus
,tib yb tib ,ti koot eh sa kcoc s’yksuh eht dnuora ylsuoiciled deniarts ediskcab siH
.delgnit pit eht sa gnihca kcoc sih ,dnim sih morf ti tup eh ,oS
ynnub eht hguoht ,yad taht ti delyts dah retxaB rehtehw erus t’nsaw eH
?tnedicca na eb ti dluoC
.mih teiuq ot kciuq saw ,revewoh ,yksuh ehT
tahw wonk t’ndid melaS hguohtla ,gnihtemos yas ot tuoba saw eH   .gniggaw liat sih
.ytisrevinu dlo eht fo noitrop doog a revo
yas dluoc meht fo rehtie
ydaer erew yeht ecno
– elbixelf saw eh os ,efil sih ni noitcerid a evah t’ndid melaS
– delliw eh sa htiw
thgit eht ,tsrif ffo tog ohw retxaB saw ti ,yllautcA
erom a morf esor taht yrc a ro bos a neeb evah thgim tI
,spih sih dnuof swap s’tibbar eht sa denaom retxaB ”,esruoc fO“
,meht erofeb tuo dehcterts seitilibissop fo dlrow a teY
kcoc s’yksuh eht gnidir ylwols ,spih sih dekcor eh sa tem seye riehT
ro gniraew saw eh tahw fo sseldrager ,doog dekool retxaB kniht syawla dluow eH
dah eh wenk retxaB ,esruoc fO
saw tI .meht neewteb llaw enots eht no wap sih eciton tub pleh
:denrecnoc saw eh sa raf sa yako saw taht tub ,taht od ton dluoc tfahs siH
naem ti did tahw tub
.nmutuA eht ni
.htmraw dna trofmoc eht gniyojne
.neht neve esolc mih gnidloh
.taht naht erom yna did eno on
,ereht demriuqs eh
.ylthgils os reve pu depmulp ti sa esab eht gnildarc
,gniog tpek melaS os ,pu
erusaelp fo skcohs cirtcelE
dah eh :nrob eb ot ti detnaw evah dluow eh sa etiuq ton saw ydob sih fi nevE
,deklat evah dluoc yehT
.htrig lluf sti ot gnitalfni erofeb egassap lana s’ynnub eht otni knus neeb dah ti fi sa ton saw ti dna
.rekihhctiH flowereW ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
ll’uoY .flesmih dlot eh ,yako s’tI
,ria eht ni gnuh taews dna xes fo tnecs thgil ehT
.rehtegot ti ni htob ,meht fo owt eht saw ti esuaceB .dluow yeht dnA
s’ynnub ehT .taorht sih fo kcab eht otni dnuorg pit eht sa tluciffid saw ti
t’nod I .oot htuos nwod krow erom s’ereht tuB“
.ti nees t’ndah eh tub
erofeB …wonk uoy ,ti od ot emit evah llits ew ebyaM
.tuo ti krow dluow yeht dna
kcab rewol s’ynnub eht fo evruc eht otni ylteews gnidlof eno
”…haey…mmm…s’ti tuB
…evah dluohs ew ,yrros m’I ,melaS
.esle enoemos htiw elbatrofmoc taht tlef reven d’eH
,meht edisni gninethgit tsul
.mih rof neeb reven dah tI .mih rof t’nsaw tI   .sdeen lacidem
?ytisrevinu retfa erehwesle gnivil
yojne esaelP   .yrruFoS no
taht sthguoht nwo sih ni peed os neeb dah melaS tey
.tsal ta dias melaS ”,haeY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.detnaw eh yaw tcaxe eht ni dna flesmih sa efil sih evil ot elba gnieb rof lufetarg ylerem saw tibbar rednegsnart ehT
.gnol oot rof ereht pu yats ot tfahs s’retxaB gniroda ni pu thguac oot saw melaS hguoht
,revewoh ,meht tuoba saw tnemom ehT
.nwod dna pu gnikorts
”?owt ro keew rehtona rof ti evah uoy t’ndiD“
.spil s’melaS fo eerf yltew gnignirps pit eht
,llaw eht no kcab denael eH
.ot drah taht lla gniyrt t’nsaw tibbar eht ,riaf eb ot ,hguoht
,repeed gnihtemos
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
hguohtla ,tsehc s’yksuh eht no detser ylikahs swap s’melaS   .reilrae hcum
,ylwols denrut elzzum siH
,spih sih gnikcor mih dah
,meht neewteb teiuq eht ,taht ta doog neeb syawla
.reverof ereht eb ot tnaw t’ndid eh tey
.tlef eh woh wonk neve t’ndid tibbar eht ,lleH   .yaw emas eht
.gnihtyna edih t’ndid yeht hguoht ,no srexob sih dah llits yksuh ehT   ”…seY …hA“
,ffo yalp ot ysae neeb evah dluoc tI
ylelos ti ni htob erew yeht ,neht litnU .retteb eht roF
.mrof sih revo ylgniroda gnikar
gnihtemos htiw gnikrow reerac a otni evom retteb sih rof ylbisnes gnitiaw
.si siht lla s’taht
sgniht elttil gnisnes
.ylisae erom htrof dna kcab edils ot wap s’melaS gniwolla dna htgnel sih nwod gnilbbird muc-erp eht
”?ti si ,neht ti si siht ,oS“
.mih hguorht dellor ysatsce sa thgiled htiw gnimmurht ydob sih ,flesmih rof strap tseb eht lla dah eH
.seye sih fo srenroc eht ni erutsiom fo netsilg eht gnirongi
,ydob sih hguorht murht gnihca na tnes taht muc-erp s’yksuh eht morf eugnot sih no ssenkcils a saw erehT
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.retpahc txen rieht etirw ot
.kcen s’melaS fo kcab eht ot nwod yaw rieht gnikrow neve
.yletaidemmi meht detterger melaS dna
,seye esoht ni flesmih esol ot detnaw eH
.waj sih fo enil eht pu ylecin gnidlof sregnif sih
hguoht ,wap s’melaS otni depmuh retxaB
,oN .deremmah traeh s’melaS
.stops thgir eht lla tih ot gnimees eugnot sih fo pal yreve ,yletarepsed
hguoht ,ekat dluoc eh htgnel s’retxaB fo hcum woh tsuj gnirolpxe
ffo eb ot gniog ,ylekil tsom ,erew yeht nehw
,erom neve tnemom eht yojne ot detnaw eh teY
,dekil rehtar eh taht ydob s’yksuh eht ot ssentfos a saw erehT
msagro tuoba ton saw tI
aera retsecuolG eht ot
,krow fo dlrow eht otni
,eltneg a ni spil sih gnilaes ,meht neewteb ecnatsid eht desolc dna
uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
.repeed dna repeed knis flesmih gnittel ,tnemom yreve yojne ot detnaw eh tub
,yojne ot yksuh eht fo erom hcum os saw ereht nehw ton ,yllaer toN
.ereht thgil ot emoc dah gnihton fi neve ,saw eh
dah evird xes siH
,tibbar eht morf noitalucaje on saw erehT
tol lufwa na eb ot gniog saw ereht rof
.flesmih gnisol yllufituaeb ,s’retxaB fo taht htiw ecnesse sih dlem ot
noisnet eht htiw ,retxaB dnA
,mM“ .gnihctiwt eson ,detnurg melaS ”…sleef taht
saw yksuh eht htiw detautafni yltfos ,ylteiuq sa saw eh snosaer ynam eht fo eno tsuj saw taht tuB
,elttil a yb ,tneduts redlo na saw eH
,meht fo eno teg uoy epoh yllaer I“
.taht naht erom gnihton dna sdneirf meht fo owt eht
,rehtegot dexamilc yehT
.peets oot saw tsoc eht sa ylerup
,thgin taht gniklat hcum od ot gniog ,revewoh ,t’nerew yehT   ”.klat…ot deen eW
”.elpuoc
.uoy tnaw I .ereh pu emoC“
”.noitadommocca eht morf ffo dedaeh I
…s’tI“ .htaerb delahxe fo hsur a ni dias melaS ”,taht teg I“
.ecneirepxe derahs rieht fo gnikniht ylno
.meht neewteb avilas fo egnahcxe eht lla ta gnidnim ton dna ecap rewols a ta sgniht gnikat
dah meht neewteb pihsnoitaler gniddub a saw thguoht dah tibbar eht tahw tub
,kcoc s’yksuh eht fo daeh eht revo ylsuoiruc detrap spil s’melaS