.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.mih ekil gnihtyna kool t'nod uoy
.eltneg ylbatrofmocnu eciov reh ,dias neleH
,os dlot erew ew esuaceb detnarg rof nekat era regnol on—
stfig rieht nialpxe ot esu yeht yrots dliw revetahw taht
,weivretni eht fo gninrom eht no rebmun eht dellac I nehW
,seot sih otno esor eh dna debbob liat siH
,neve eciov ym peek ot deirt I ,raews I
.nrael ot ecnahc rehtona uoy dewo ew dezilaer ew dna
dnob sa drow ym ylno uoy reffo nac I
.enod eb nac ti taht em ot evorp neht dna
.seenk reh no swoble reh
?sekatsim ruoy ni eson ym bur ot
ni siht tuoba thguoht t'ndah I
s'enuejeL enitsuJ otni noitagitsevni deunitnoc eht
.em tel ot evah uoy tub ,uoy pleh nac I .t'nac uoy os
.daeh reh dnuora enam gniwolg tniaf a tup gnithgil kcart ehT
.weiver ot enog ev'ew smialc revetahw
.eciov s'neR yb dewollof ,psag prahs a draeh I em dniheb morF
".yriuqnI morf er'uoY"
gnitadilav yllautca morf su stneverp noihsaf emos ni sdnamed esoht fo eno yreve ,liaf tuohtiW
,yrujni na hcuot uoy nehw ehca peed-enob taht wonk uoY
.erogerge na sa bulc eht ot mih dereffo I
,aremac eht no noitnetta ym desucof I
.dnuorg eht tsniaga htrof dna kcab dekcilf liat reH
.etis siht rof weivretni tsal
,sneppah taht nehW
.rehtruf yna gniyfitsuj yrt ot sesufer ylpmis ro
:esnes evitiutni sekam aedi cisab eht ,erutluc ralucitrap yna ni ,noitacilppa eht revetahW
”ytnuoC moctahW fo hctiW ehT“
.ylpeed oot ni saw I tniop siht ta ,ssefnoc I ".sgnikrow
,llaw eno tsniaga tas retnec aidem dna VT neercs-talf A
,drow ruo yb dnats ew dna
em dniheb ysatnaf taht tup I thguoht I retfa sraey net eulb eht fo tuo em llac uoY"
,etoN s'rotidE[ ]yriuqnI
yteicos ni ecalp ro noitatneiro ro redneg—
.doog rof em dniheb saw efil ym fo trap taht thguoht I ,no sraey neT
.ruf delffur eht nwod gnihtooms detrats dna pal ym otni dnuora liat ym dellup I
.neleH ot egdab eht dessap I
,scificeps lautir rof gniksa tpek uoY
.stnemeriuqer esoht detpecca syawla ev'yeht esuaceb dedeeccus syawla evah
.elzzum s'adisserC .sM no aremac eht dna
.enips ym ot kcen ym morf llihc a dah I tey dna
,yllaer ,era su fo llA"
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.denifed yllaciripme ro devorp yltnednepedni eb dluoc taht srewsna detnaw uoy ekil tlef ti tub
.tep ,esaelp seeffoc owT"
.emarf eht ni tif t'ndid taht srae dna
sriahc gnidlof dehctamsim dna elbat nedoow sti
,os dlot neeb ev’ew esuaceb detnarg rof snosaes eht ekat regnol on ot ,ecaps dna
.esac siht ot dengissa neeb evah reven dluohs I
ytilaer fo sliated cisab yas
emalB' ,loohcs darg tfel I emit eht yB
.gninrael llits erew eW
,revewoh ,emit sihT
,noitpurretni eht rof lufetarg ,ti koot I
— dehsilbup s'ti fi
,em derongi neR tub
,tseuqer yeht epor revetahw elpoep evig
.rae ot rae morf dennirg ssenoil ehT ".detcepxenu
,detaudarg uoy ecnis gniod neeb d'uoy tahw was eW
secnedicnioc fo seires elbaborpmi ylgnikcohs sihT
.laer si cigam taht uoy ot evorp ot ekil dluow I dna neR
;ybxiB siuoL eb ot mialc uoY .neht ,eniF"
eht dekcehc dna snel eht ot pu meht dleh neve I
dna recarT ”yrerrO“ anitsirK yb
,sarua ees t'nac saremac
.rojam ruoy degnahc uoy yllautneve dna
.erutan siht fo ésopxe na nur enizagam yriuqnI sah erofeb reveN
.seitiliba nwo rieht tuoba sfeileb 'stegrat rieht etadommocca ot esufer yeht
,srenoititcarp lacigam eb ot demialc taht bulc ytisrevinu a tuoba draeh I .ylenol ,ylknarf
".esac tset ruoy s'erehT
.gnillewd yrutnec-dim yna
.su ot gniklat rof noitidnocerp drah emos
pohskrow reh ot ssecca rof gniksa rof nosaer ylno s'neleH taht dias maet sdael eht morf elif eht no tog I seton ehT
.ria-nepo gnihton
,cigam krow ot woh fo seirots rieht ot netsil ot em detivni ,wenk ydaerla I tahw em deksa yehT
.yaw emas eht strats reveileB eurT yreve htiw weivretni yrevE  ].desivda si
.sevlesruo ti dootsrednu yllaer ew hguoht sa
.eciov ym fo tuo noisnet eht peek t'ndluoc I ".yriuqnI
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
".won rof rac eht ni meht evael esaelp
,nac I uoy ot raews I ,enuejeL
,sdniM gniriuqnI ,uoy esivda eW
,delaes llits saw rabrettuN ehT .slaes
,emilbus eht ot traeh eht nepo pleh ot tfarc ruo ni ssergnoc lauxes esu I dna neR"
,hguoht ,emit sihT
.llah eht otni kcab deppets neht ,dewob tibbar ehT
.daetsni sih esu dluoc repap a ffo nekat eman rieht detnaw ohw ydobynA
,dlog saw eitwob reh tub
lanoitidartitlum er'ew tub
"?emoh ta sserd yllausu sehctiw woh siht sI
,yriuqnI ta stnemeerga ruo ronoh eW
,rotidE feihC ,noshpesoJ .M—
,recarT ”yrerrO“ anitsirK yb
,seye eulb esnetni htiw
.ytiniffaruF no revo ybboh a sa setirw ohw ,ynnuB
;steb rekcus ekat ot esufer krow fo dnik siht od taht setis tsoM
,god.ecioveht ta
"?...eno ,maerc htiw enO
.deknilb I "?em wohS"
,noitcafsitas ym ot delaes eb ot dah segakcap eht
.nac delaes a ni knird ot gnihtemos dna
.noitcennoc siht dessim maet ekatni ruo woh wonk t'nod I
.krow t'now ti ro
”ytnuoC moctahW fo hctiW ehT“
.ssenoil eht ot kcab denrut I ,thgis fo tuo ylefas saw eh ecnO
.spil ym morf llef sdrow ehT ".tsac
le na saw noisivelet eht gnicaF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
?enola ti evael dluohs uoy gniwonk
.nihtiw rehtruf gniyalp cisum eht revo draeh eb ot hguone ylduol tsuj ekops eh dna
.gnihton dnuof ew evarg s'rehtom ym no raews I tub ,tsilkcehc weivretni-erp eht nar I .ekaL resiW yb pu
,hsilbup ot eciwt su detpmorp evah sresivda lagel ruo ,esac siht nI
.nioj ot deirt I dna
.em sdrawot denoitom ehs sa noitseuq gniregnil a ni eciov reh detfil ehS
"?em htiw tnaw uoy od tahW"
.deciffus syawla sah ytirgetni 'stsilanruoj ruo
.lautir eht gnirud dedlofdnilB
.retteb eht erom eht
.hguoht ,scitnames ro
,tfel eht deipucco erutcip yM
.ecaf eht ni em gnirats ,saw ti ereh woN
.rehto ro lleps emos tsac evah ot demialc yllanoisacco dna
,wonk wohemos lla yeht taht s'tI
,noisivelet eht no rezilausiv eht otni derats dna tas I
.sduarf sa su esopxe ot yrt ot gnimoc erew uoy
.gninraw tsrif ym saw tahT
,noitartsurf reehs fo tuo pu evag eW
.ffuts evom ot skcos ni gnieotpit
setis suoigiler cihtiloen no segami deredneg-driht morf
.sM" .cisum eht revo elbidua tsuj ot deppord eciov reh dna
:os era yeht yas ew esuaceb era tub
,taht ekil sllac dloc morf kcab raeh ylerar eW
.gnola yalp saw od dluoc ew tsael eht derugif eW
.elims tsetniaf eht htiw srae denettalf dna worb deworruf ym ot dednopser ssenoil ehT "?em denommus uoY"
.drow eht tuo dekohc I "?yrros er'uoY"
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,uoy erofeb lautir krow em gnittel ot tnesnoc uoy od
,dluoc ew tahw nialpxe ot deirt eW
;tnesnoc seriuqer cigam ym tub
.ytiniffaruF no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,krow dehsilbup tsrif s’oK si ytnuoC moctahW fo hctiW
,stoob dna dratoel kcalb a erow ssenoil eht ,neR ekiL
.em ot swap reh tuo dleh ssenoil ehT ".enoD"
.ytiluderc ruo deniarts dna
.nossel yrotsih a htiw htiw
:oot ,tniop taht desserts eH
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
,uoy stel yriuqnI ,tniop taht tA
.moc tod rettiwT fo yletal ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer ,ynnuB oK
.elbatrofmoc flesruoy ekam ,esaelP"
,koon gninid llams a saw thgir eht oT
.meht teg og ot uoy ksa ot dah ev'dluow I
.tuo hcaer ot deerga I dna neR tub
.emiL teiD s'ttibseN fo nac a dna rabrettuN ananab A" .gab repap eht pu dleh I
noihsaf ssucsid ot ereh emoc t'ndid uoY"
,flesmeht stcidartnoc
kcans degakcap-erp fo dnarb revetahw gnirb ot em deksa eh dna
"?tseuqer ruoy llifluf ot redro ni ,smret ym no
s'enuejeL enitsuJ uoy gnirb ew
.wap hcae ni gum a
,ylneve dednopser neleH
debbud dah srekrowoc ym noisserpxe na ni tes elzzum reh
"?erom yna raeb elam a gnieb ton nialpxe uoy od woH
emit ot siht dnetxe ot hcterts a fo hcum os ti sI
.t'ndid I dneterp t'nac I
.railimaf tbuod on era sredaer yriuqnI
.eno rof ,ezigolopa ot detnaw I"
,stsilautir citatsce
,evitcnitsni eb ot smees srettam yldlrowrehto
;reveileB eurT a neeb reven dah I
,etis eht no sserdda eht deliam-e eW
neht" ,ylwols dias I
uoy od tahw ,dias I"
s'tsihposoraT fo seussi kcab dleh sevlesmeht sevlehs eht elihw
.weivretni elohw siht no liab ot detnaw tsuj em fo trap emoS
,weivretni na rof emit dna etad a tes ot gniyrt si maet tcatnoc ruo fo eno elihW
,taht ekil tlef sdrow s'neleH
,tnemom taht nI ".enuejeL .sM
.tellaw ym fo tuo em deussi etis eht ssap sserp eht gnillup ,deilper I
trats s'tel ,neht ,dnim t'nod uoy fI"
.msicitpeks emertxe htiw daer ot tuoba er'uoy gnihtyreve ekat ot
.teem ot gnilliw etiuq erew yeht dna
.esle gnihtyna ro ,senohp ,sredrocer ,saremac gnirb t'ndluoc ew yas t'ndid yeht tub
?gnisserp pots t'ndluoc uoy taht esiurb a dah reve uoy evah
fo pordkcab eht tsniaga yranidro yllufniap
em ta pu derats otohp eht ni cennef ehT
.dopirt eht pu gnittes gnitrats dna
,evloser ruo detset ,ecneitap ruo deirt evah stcejbus ruO
"?cigam krow nac uoy kniht uoy sekam tahW
;epat no derutpac I wonk I hcum tahT
:etoN s'rotidE[  2 fo
maet sdael s'yriuqnI nehW
.noitseuq rehtona tub ,egnellahc a ton
.hcuoc eht no kcab denael dna delims I ".cigam
1 traP ,ynnuB oK dna
.neleH ot denrut I ,moor gnivil eht fo tuo saw eh sa noos sA
,stca xes ticilpxe fo snoitciped sniatnoc elcitra sihT :tpircstsoP
.eveileb ot ssengnilliw a dna
.noisivelet eht no rezilausiv gnilriws eht morf yawa gninrut tuohtiw dias ehs ",emocleW"
,tibbar eht morf eeffoc reh koot neleH
.cigam klat ot detnaw uoy thguoht I"
.delims neleH "?woh em wohS"
.enohp ym pu dleh I ".ekil d'uoy fi
.daetsni ,uoy no sucof s'teL"
,rood tnorf eht ta ti detniop dna taes kcab eht ni aremac oediv eno pu tes I .naelc kcab emac esuoh eht edistuo sgnidrocer oidua cinosartlu dna cinosarfnI
— ereht pohskrow reh ot ssecca evah dluow neleH
ni nees thgim uoy dnik eht ,moor gnivil til-ylthgirb a otni gnidael
,dnamed emos ekam lliw etadidnac eht
.aremac eht pu tes I elihw deilper I
emalb lliw sreveileB eurT eht
riahc gnikcor s'neleH raen hcuoc eht no taes a koot I
I woN .siht dettops evah dluohs enoemoS
,ehcysp ym fo kcab eht ni erehwemos
,nac uoy kniht t'nod uoy won thgir dna ,ti ot emoc ot evah uoY
.sthgil teloivartlu oN .saremac oN
,eruliaf syawla s'ti dna — eruliaf yna
,seitrap rennid dleh yltnerappa sdraziw nredom neve taht emit eht ta gnikoj rebmemer I ".ytilaer
hcihw htiw senizagam tlucco
".elpoep fo tol a truh sah etisbew 'sreyolpme ruoy ,wonk uoY"
;neht kcab ybxiB yb tnew I
em fo tuo lanosrep yrev gnihtemos deggard dah adisserC .sM .truh saw I tub
.cilati etaciled a ni edis thgir eht no etad eussi eht dna ogol s'yriuqnI htiw
.efil ysatnaf evitca yrev a dah I
.ssik thgil a rof ralloc sih yb nwod mih dellup neht
.hgis detarepsaxe na tuo tel neleH
"?delaes eb yeht dluohs yhw dna ,esoht deen I od yhW"
tsuj erew yeht taht shtnom wef a retfa raelc saw ti tub
,em ot eno dereffo dna dehcaorppa yltnelis eH
"?deksa ew tahw gnirb uoy diD
,yromem gnol a sah bulC xineohP ehT .sruoy dna ,eniM"
knip gninrut srae ym fo edisni eht morf ro ",tep"
.yawa gniklaw erofeb em ta delims eh sa
.swalc delif ylluferac esopxe ot sselregnif erew sevolg reh dna
'.ecaf xiv gnitser'
.moc tod rettiwT fo yletal
,sfires bals ni egde pot eht detanimod eltit dna eman yM
,llat seirots owt saw esuoh s'adisserC
,moor eht derednaw seye reh ylteiuq tas ssenoil ehT
.rebmun enohp a htiw retal yad a deilper enoemos ,emit siht tub
,wollof ot rewsna ruoy fo txetnoc lluf eht dnatsrednu tonnac uoy wonk I"
.yriuqnI ton dna bulC xineohP eht ton
.sepyt tlucco demialcorp fles rehto ynam os ekil daer ti dna
,srezisehtnys golana htiw ecaps eht dellif srekaeps neddiH
,wap ym rednu dereviuq liat elohw yM ".lleps a
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
;tnetnoc ruo ezilairotide ot yrassecen ti tlef reven evah eW
.ma I ,seY" "?yrros er'uoY
,dna derob tsuj saw I
— esuoh reh yb deppots ew fi tseisae eb d'ti dias yehT
",esiwrehto ereh uoy detivni evah t'ndluow I" ".oediv
rotaripsnococ a dah yeht ro
.gnidnatshtiwton stuobaerehw s'adisserC neleH ro
,gniod tuoba deggarb I gnihtemos s'ereht wonk uoy
;ti htiw enif m'I"
,ecrof yb eduerfnedahcs gnitcartxe fo ssenisub eht ni eb ton yam yriuqnI ".cigam
,emit emas eht dnuora saw I erehw gniksa deppots yehT
"?adisserC .sM er'uoY" .delims I ".enitsuJ
.epoh dna snoitseuq erew dah ew llA
.snoitartsnomed rieht od ot esufer thgirtuo yeht ,netfO
.smra reh deppord dna ssih enilef a tuo evag ehs ,stnemom wef a retfa dna ,hguoht
.deddon tibbar ehT
".efas er'yeht wonk ot tnaw ll'uoy dna
:snosaer rieht evah t'nod yeht taht ton s'tI
,gninraw dnoces ym saw tahT
.elytsefil eht etiuq evah owt uoY"
,daeh ym tsniaga kcab ylthgit dellup dah srae yM
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ecaps eht fo elddim eht ni gnitaolf sgabnaeb wef a dna snamotto deffutsrevo htiw ,hcuoc lanoitces depahs-
.ssenkrad raen otni pu tnew esacriats a ,rood tnorf eht edisni tsuJ
oK aka noilykciN dna
,ybxiB siuoL fo ytitnedi eht ot seit lautirips tuc I nehW
.epor a gniggut fi sa ,reh sdrawot ti dekcilf ehS .reh fo tnorf ni ria eht ni dnuora ti delruc neht ,wap ym desaeler neleH
.noitasrevnoc fo tcejbus etirovaf nwo rieht s'enoyreve tub
.srednuof eht retfa seetcudni fo puorg tsrif eht ni saw I"
.hctiw a si su fo rehtien ,yaw eht yb ,dnA
.uoy llet tsuj ton
.sgnikrow tseb ym fo enO"
.pu-sdap htob ,erom ecno em ot swap reh tuo dleh ehS ".em
.hcnelcnu ot selcsum eht decrof dna htaerb peed a koot I tub
ot si sevlesruo eb ot
.esnopser ym deredisnoc I elihw ti deppis dna
.noitasrevnoc siht gnidrocer m'I ,deerga sA"
.derettum I ",enif si kcalB"
,uoy no ti ecrof t'nac I
,lanoitnetni saw ti gniveileb tsomla flesym dnuof I
.kooh eht ffo enoyreve stel tahT
.esor ehs sa dias ssenoil eht ",esaelp ,neleH"
”ytnuoC moctahW fo hctiW ehT“   yojne esaelP
"?bulC xineohP eht tuoba raeh uoy did erehW"
tnatsissa s'naicigam egats a neewteb yawflah emutsoc a gniraew ,rood eht ta em deteerg ruf nat htiw tibbar A
,tsap reh morf nur lliw enitsuJ rehtehw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.edisni mih wollof ot em rof denoitom eh dna ,rood eht ot kcab emac I ecno edisa deppets neR
?gnihtyna uoy gnirb tep ym evah I naC
",doog sdnuos eeffoC" "?eeffoC ?retaW
.aremac oediv eht ot txen ti dehsats dna rac eht ot kcab doof eht koot I os ,yaw eht fo tuo pets ot evom on edam neR ".kcab
.em tsurt ot nosaer on evah uoy wonk osla I tub
,srewop rieht htiw serefretni teloivartlu
.gnirehtoms tlef ssendnik 'ssenoil ehT ".ma
,tnemom a desuap ehS ".noitidart klof
.rewsna ot esoohc uoy revewoh ,elbatrofmocnu emoceb uoy sa noos sa drowefas ot uoy rewopme I dna
,meht htiw gnola yalp ot deirt I
.delaeh ecnis gnol dah thguoht I racs a no gnisserp
.roinuj a saw I nehw denioj neR
.delims tibbar ehT "?—yhw oS"
.tuo ti dleh eh sa gniwob
,em htiw edisni ekat ot dopirt a dna
.elzzum reh no gnirevawnu elims reh
.gniyas saw ehs tahw tuo ekam t'ndluoc I ,srae eseht htiw neve tub
,mih gniksa rebmemer tsuj I
.evol I yas I sa evol I .ma I yas I ohw ma I
.desolc llits saw ti wohs ot aremac eht fo tnorf ni nwod-edispu nac eht denrut I dna
recarT "yrerrO" anitsirK yb
.enitsuJ em llaC"
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,dekrow gnihtyreve woh uoy llet ot su gniksa tpek uoY
.yriuqnI rof krow uoY"
eht gnignahc fo elbapac sehctiw"
;dias I tahw s'taht wohs oediv eht teL
,sdleiy noitagitsevni eht revetahw hsilbup ot
,denworf dna worb reh deworruf ehS
mih dellac neleH nehw hctorc s'tibbar eht sdrawot gnicnalg morf em pots t'ndid tahT
;hguoht ,esoht hcuot ot tnaw t'nod I"
.adisserC neleH tas
dnoces a tuo tog neht
?era yeht yas ew sa eb yam
,ereh tcejbus eht era uoY"
,drawrof denael dna delims noil ehT ".nossel
:driht ym saw rewsna siH
.swap sih pu dleh dna gab ym ta decnalg eH ".yltcerid
.detcepxenu gnihtyna rof ekoj gninnur a emoceb dah 'ybxiB
".netsil ot ereh tsuj m'I"
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.erehwyna su teem ot yppah eb d'yeht tub
.cigam krow nac I
eno siht piks esaelp
",rotagitsevni dleif roines ,enuejeL enitsuJ"
noitercsid yvaeH
.gninekrad eciov reh
.scisyhp fo swal eht yfed taht emos gnidulcni
.egap tnorf s'yriuqnI no gnieb ni detseretni eb d'ehs fi gniksa
.devom spil reh dna ,seye ym otni dezag ehS
.yniturcs fo dnik thgir eht rednu trapa sllaf
.snosaer gnorw eht lla rof syawedis gniog weivretni na fo elddim eht ni saw
.seton ym ni meht derots dna stohs neercs koot I ;"adisserC .H" yb oga sraey neetfif thguob neeb dah ytreporp eht dewohs sdrocer ytnuoC moctahW
.gnihton yllacisab rof deksa maet s'adisserC neleH
,degdelwonkca staevac esoht llA
.gnihctiwt ylbisiv pitliat eht
,wap rehto eht no ,maet s'yriuqnI
.tnetni rieht ton dna sdrow eht tuoba lla saw ti ekil
;aedi s'neR saw tI" .delkcuhc neleH
.ytilaer fo cirbaf
seeweivretni ruo htiw ngis ew tcartnoc yreve ni s'ti esuaceb siht gnihsilbup ylno er'eW
.roolf doowdrah eht no htrof dna kcab dekcilf pitliat detfut reH
".su tel ll'uoy fi ,si tahT
.enitsuJ eb tsum uoY"
,sdniM gniriuqnI ".yrros m'I
.rohtua-oc a sa ybxiB dah yrarbil s'bulc eht ni srepap eht fo driht lluf a
.cinap cinatas yad-tneserp eht ot
.selkraps revlis htiw dettod eitwob etihw a dah eh dna
,tcartnoc fo hcaerb elbissop gnitic
.yranidro eht fo tuo gnihton pu denrut saremac teloivartlu dna derarfnI
.dnuora em evah ot tnaw t'ndid taht hcnub yeuqilc a
.rewolf der thgirb a erow eh ,rae eno dniheb dekcuT
serutaef s'yriuqnI
.gniliec eht ta gnizag saw ehs ekil dekool ehs ,woleb morf tohS
,dnuora drow eht worht ot sevol yriuqnI wonk I
.selytsefil evitanretla fo sdnik lla ot em deruni dah yriuqnI ta sraey yM
.tsac d'I dias I lleps emos
,sehctiw sevlesmeht gnillac sklof rof hcraes enilno na hguorht etisbew reh dnuof d'eW
,meht tcepsni nac uoY
.llah niam rieht ni gnignah s'tiartrop ym
,ngilA dna ylretrauQ
klat ot tnaw uoY
;ediw tnew seye yM ".llah
.nwod em kcart ot dediced dah
,mraw oot emoceb tsuj dah moor ehT
.nwo ym ni swap reh koot dna hcuoc eht morf esor I ".ees em tel dna
.kcalc ot hteet ym rof hguone drah tuhs deppans elzzum ym dna ,wap a pu dleh neleH "—
htiw ssenreeuq fo noitaicossa ehT
,noitartsnomed eht retfa ,nehT
,yhw swollof yhw swollof yhW
,meht thguorb t'ndah uoy fI"
.llew sa ti derongi I tub
.gnivaeh saw tsehc yM
.dluohs I taht detseggus msilanoisseforP
".enuejeL .sM eb tsum uoY"
.snoitidnocerp yrassecen eht gniteem ton no
,od ot deirt I tahw em lleT" .sraey
,raW laniF eht dnuora morf sgnitniap notskcoR amroN ni nees dnik eht ,riahc gnikcor nedoow dlo na nI
,oot ,sevaw dna dniw eht taht yas ot
?ti t'nsi ,sreveileB eurT gniknubed si boj ruoY
?seog eloh tibbar eht raf woh tsuj tuo dnif dna esuoh eht otni kcab neR dna neleH wollof ro
.yltcerid ssertsiM ksa ot tnaw ll'uoy
srePRAL ysatnaf dethgils fo puorg siht wohemos taht
.uoy dlot I" .dehgual neleH
,daeh reh gnuh dna deppots ehS "—tub ,nac I"
ruf tessur trohs ni derevoc elzzum enipluv nael
.ratla na erofeb gnidnats erew ehs fi sa
.su morf raeh ot yppah saw enohp eht no ekops yeht mohw htiw nosrep eht ,hcuot ni tog
"?oidua dedrocer htiw enif er'uoy emussa I ,oslA"
,935RS fo ffo snrut wef a yawevird trid gnol a fo dne eht ta gnittis ,edaçaf enotsdleif a htiw
,uoy wohs ot woh tuo derugif ev'ew kniht ew
,od ot eerga t'nod uoy gnihtyna od uoy ekam ot yrt t'now I taht
",bulC xineohP eht ta saw I
.kcab esoht tup ev'uoy ecno ni uoy tel ll'I ;neR m'I
.sretroper pot ruo fo eno su tsoc enoemos
.gab yrecorg repap a htiw gnola
,lautir a rof meht deen thgim uoY"
,noissimrep ruoy htiw ,dna oiduA
,thgir eht no gninepo na ot sriats eht tsap del taht yawllah eht sdrawot gninoitom
.ezag ym gniteem ton
"?uoy  nac ,t'nac uoY —uoy t'naC ?tahW"
.duht a htiw liat ym no em deppord lawardhtiw dna lained neddus ehT ".tinmaD"
naeporuE nrehtron fo srewollof ton
,elbaffeni gnihtemos ...gnihtemoS ".esrevinu
traeh nepo na saw dedeen cigam eht tahw taht nialpxe ot deirt eW
,swap ym ekat nehT"
,gnirepsihw reh raeh dluoc I
wonk uoy fI" .thguoht ni tsol
,sdniM gniriuqnI ,uoy llet em tel dna ,ydaer t'nsaw I nehw
.ssenetarebiled fo gnimees eht dah
.tnetnoc ruo tcarter ew gnidnamed tnemssarah lagel pots ot esualc taht ekovni ot dah reve ylno ev'ew ,won litnU .tahw rettam on
,elzzum sih no nirg evissam a dah eH
,slautir fo egnar rediw a mrofrep ot saw
.daeh sih dewob dna moor eht otni deppets tibbar ehT ".ssertsiM ,gnimoC"
.snoisulcnoc nwo ruoy ward ,sdniM gniriuqnI
,ytisrevinU tropegdirB ta saw I elihw :nialpxe oT
,noitingocerp slavir taht noitiutni na htiw
",enuejeL .sM ,bulc eht trats depleh I"
.esrevinu eht htiw eno ta etats citatsce eht
.niaga gniraeppasid erofeb dewob dna pu doots neht
.retal meht deen thgim uoY
tsac uoy pleh ot ekil d'eW
,reilrae ti gnissim rof dezigolopa ekops I mohw htiw nosrep eht
,tenalpruF ta esahcrup rof elbaliava ,slevon dehsilbup owt sah ohw
a skram rieht sevig ,nrut ni ,tahT
,ekops ehs sa sdrow reh dedrigrednu sativarg emos
.devres noitidnocerp hcae esoprup tahw sksa reweivretni eht
,htiw tem si noitanalpxe yrevE
,rood eht ni deraeppaer neR
,oda rehtruf tuohtiw os dna
,nialpxe t'nac rehtie tcejbus eht litnu
.ecnanossid evitingoc rieht rof evlav esaeler
.gnihtyreve gnidrocer saw ti em gnillet thgil neerg a dna neercs kcab sti no oediv dah I ,retal etunim A
.tser eht detanimod sevlehskoob dna
.retsemes txen eht etatS nogerO ot devom I dna
,xetal yssolg erew sgnikcots dna dratoel kcalb ehT .raewhsitef dna
,dias yeht ,etis eht fo draeh d'yeht esruoc fO
.lla ta doog yrev leef t'ndid taht