”,ainrofilaC ni lagel saw ffuts eht gnikoms thguoht I dnA“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
.em derussaer thgiwD ”,esiwrehto emussa t’ndluow eW“
?em eldnah uoy naC :nexiV_ydeeN
si yrots s’yadoT dna
!ssel on ,rof erac t’ndid eh seitirahc roF
.ssa ruoy kcik annog m’I ,ti s’tahT“
em dellepmoc gnihtemoS
gnihctiwt ,pit rae na desserac ylhguor sregnif siH
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”,oda rehtruf tuohtiw woN“
.erew snoitarepo rieht lufsseccus dna dezilartnec woh erew setnaligiv tenretnI eb-dluow rehto yna ro seloh$$A eht morf meht detarapes tahW
.ecnerwaL deman yksuh nairebiS elbaticxe
.odnoc yruxul a ni evil t’ndid I
.ainrofilaC nrehtron ni emoh retsof ssalc-rewol tsedom a ni pu werg em ekil nexiv denahpro nA
eno siht piks esaelp
naom u lit tnuc taht dnuop annaw :yddaDfloW_FTD kcuf ho :yddaDfloW_FTD
fo elpuoc a ot ti etanoD“
,nosdnarg ruoy gnitaert er’yeht woh raeh ot yrros ma I“
t’nod tsuJ .hguone ti ekil ot gniog m’I kniht I…tub
.eciov ym gnignahc decitcarp I sa yb tnew syaD
.erp htiw gnippird yltnerappa dna gnislup
”!deruces si noitanod suoreneg s’llahsraM .rM
.enil rehto eht dellif rethguaL
.meht gnoma sdrac straeH fo ecA htiw dellif kced a dna ,sloot gnitekcopkcip emos ,tik puekam ruf A
.rood eht ta deralg llahsraM nodroG
.ybab ,kcab saw straeH fo ecA ehT
.rotaregirfer eht ot depat
,drah eb nac elggurts eht elihW
.sdrow s’redael tsivitkcah motnahp eht sdrawot gnitfird flesti dnuof noitnetta ym tey ,krow sti gniod deunitnoc recart ehT
.remmus hcae snainrofilaC yb nees eb ot thgis gnimussanu rehtonA
laisrevortnoc…erom gnihsilbup neeb ev’yeht ,ynapmoc eht ni noitisop gib a mih evag dad sih ecnis revE
.arb ym hguorht sboob ym fo eno debbarg neht
.erutaerc-flah tenretni ruoy
.erutcip rehtona mih gnidnes daetsni ,erac t’ndid dna lanoitnetni saw ti fi wonk t’ndid I
tnatropmi na s’meht fo enO“
,emit emas eht ta tey ,ylleb reeb sih no nees eb dluoc gnibmilc etaroproc dna egairram yppahnu na fo llot ehT
.ylisaenu deddon tegrat ruo dna ,tnemevom eht ta niaga delworg raeb ehT .ksed renroc a no gniyl esacfeirb sih rof dehcaer ylsuoituac llahsraM
raews I“ .nigeb skrowretaw demlehwrevo eht tel neht ,eciov ym ot gnirevauq eht ni dedda I
,po ro( boj eht rof deraperp I ,oS
?yxes # moor eht s’tahw :nexiV_ydeeN
?em fo tseb eht tog moderob ebyaM
?tnes I rebmun moor eht teg t’ndid
.tcepxe tsael d’eh gnitaeb mrif a rof ydaer ,edis rehto eht no ralgrub a ees ot gnitcepxe-flah ,gnikniht tuohtiw ni tnew I ”...tihS“
”?uoy er’kcuf eht ohW“
.stnelat dna ecneirepxe ruoy fo namow a eriuqer seugaelloc ym dna eM
”.dlrow eht ot egnahc lautcaf ,laer ekam dluoc ew ,rehtegoT
,skrow lufsseccus suoiverp sa nettirw-llew sa ton ylpmis ro ,nemow-itna ,yag-itna t’nera sretcarahc dna semeht eht nehW
.morf laets ot desu I elpoep emas eht ekil tsuj ,dlrow eht ni selbuort eht lla morf yawa delbbub tneps eb ylpmis
?erom ecno gnihtemos gnilaets yllanif fo thguoht eht ta yddig leef I did hcum woH .yletulosbA
,rehtegot skrow nwo rieht gnisitrevda erutnev tnioj a
.nedE nemraC .sM ,uoy eracs ot yrroS
.tuo ti dellup I dna
,noissim eht gnirud elbissop sa sruf wef sa htiw gnitcaretni dna wol gnipeek eriuqer t’ndid I fI
.nwotrekaL raen dnuopmoc etomer a gnidliub morf noitazinagro ycamerpus erovinrac tneloiv rehtar a dessarah yeht
elihw em no nworg d’taht tcelaid nainrofilaC eht ezisahpme ot erus edam I
knim eht dehsiw em fo edis teiuq ehT
.tluciffid morf raf saw noitnevnoc eht gnidniF
.’em dlo elttil roop‘
.yrrow t’nod tub ,yltsenoh ,uoy dnif ot elihw a kooT
ro fo draeh reven d’I sretcarahc sa deyalpsoc emoS
.puorg tsivitkcah eht rof tcepser emos dloh t’ndid I yas ot toN
.flow eht ta delrans ’dnabsuh‘ yM
.drawretfa rewohs dloc ecin a dna krap ybraen s’muinimodnoc eht dnuora llorts lausac a yb dewollof ,nwad erofeb ruoh na pu gnikaw yb detrats gninrom lausu yM
lla dna eh gnihtemos rof yldnilb leef dna sserd ym fo meh eht tfil ot nwod dehcaer llahsraM
,)izzucaj wen a htiw eno( smoorhtab owt ,smoordeb eerht
”.etad tsal ruo retfa detsisni eH .gnivigsknahT siht ylimaf sih tisiv emoc ot em deksa tsuj miT
”.noitcerid yna ni gniws t’nod I .elbbub ruoy tsrub ot yrros m’I ,etad a ni detseretni er’uoy esuaceb s’ti fI“
.elbaliava era sloot revetahw gnisu ot
,lliH ytrebiL ,sallertsE saL neewteb llac eht gnicart tpek dna boj sti did ti ,llitS
,hO“ ”.si yenom gnissim eht erehw ot seitirohtua eht ffo pit ot gniog ton er’eW
.gnorw gnihtyna od t’ndid eH“
selggurts lla ekil
.srae ym neewteb deppat yltbus eh dna ,cinap neddih ni
,gninaemed netfo dna ,riafnu dna
.elbapac llits er’uoy wonk ot ekil dluow ew neht ,ecnanoS :er fo rebmem a gnimoceb ni detseretni er’uoy fI“
”?…ssiM ,yadot ylevol kool uoY“
t’ndluoc I ,llew…margorp gnicart eht dna ,hcum sa eciwt tsoc retupmoc ehT
!KCONK !KCONK !KCONK !KCONK !KCONK .emit no ni thgir deppets
?tnemeriter ot eud gnidaf erew stcnitsni ym ebyaM
”,nahtanoJ ot riafnu gnieb si .E.L.C.U“ .llim romur eht ro secirp yrecorg eht yb detanimod noitasrevnoc a ni gnitluser yllausu ,hcnurb rof tuo tae ot snoitativni ’srobhgien ym fo eno gnitpecca ro sepicer tsafkaerb wen neewteb detnemirepxe I ,nehT
,noitnevnoc nwotnwod eht erofeb keew A
.ffo denrut era senohporcim ro saremac eht revenehw sweiv ralimis dloh ot deromur neeb sah nodroG
.VR dekrap a ot em del eh
ekil raeppa em edam rufdaeh deliatynop ym ot skaerts elprup fo owt ro hsad a dna
?setunim eerht ni evirra dluow evitarepo eht yas yeht t’ndiD
.elzzum thgirb ym no nworf eht sa kciuq sa tnew dna emac thguoht dehtuom-luof ehT
.sgniht fo emehcs dnarg eht ni em dedivorp tsieh eht tahw ot naeco eht ni pord a ,srallod derdnuh-thgie ylhguor tsoc tI
retsaf og ot erawtfos eht ta sreggad gniralg seye ym etipsed desumeb tsomla gnidnuos
.rebmemer ot gnirehtob deirt I naht retsaf gaw liat ym edam feihcsim ot gninruter fo thguoht ehT .ytnelP
.eciov cinortcele eht deilper
.desoporp eh ”,uoy ot pu siht ekam nac…hu I ,haeY“ ”?reffO“
.gnilasan nretsewdiM emos ni gnireppep
.erugif rellat sih dniheb rood eht gnisolc retfa drawrof decnavda neht
,ekil eht ro dooH niboR yalp ot ytinutroppo eht dah reveN
,dediced I ,gnihgiS
.etaudarg egelloc a naht redlo on demees ehS
”?keew siht dennalp evah uoy od tahw ,nemraC ,oS“
.erofeb esuac doog a rof ffuts elots reveN“
,sicoV sumoD yb
.emit doog a dah gnidnetta enoyreve
.draug ytiruces s’muinimodnoc eht llac neht ,nib gnilcycer eht ni epolevne alinam eht ssot ot em dlot tI
,swap gib sih ni enohporcim eht dleh gnineve eht rof tegrat ym
.yako tnew lenap ehT
.yawyna llac eht gnicart deirt I yhw saw hcihW
.uoy egduj lliw ydobon
tih dna rebmun eht deretne neht
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,deksa I ”?remrahc eht uoy t’nera
”.ecnahc rehtona mih evig ot naeD eht ecnivnoc pleh lliw ohw reywal doog a swonk dnabsuh yM“
,noihsaf tsenoh na ni deilper I ”,tnereffid…s’tI“
,dnaaaaaaaA“ .enohptrams eraps a no tnuocca knab dnuorgrednu na hguorht kcehc eht gnihsac tuoba tnew ecnerwaL
,flow lufrewop ,detrevrep
,deggurhs eh ”,em rof llew yrev skroW“
.sdradnats lauxes yb evisserpmi sa dezirogetac eb dluoc sih ,emitefil ym ni nees d’I scip kcid wef eht lla fO
wenk I dna ,esrup ym ni gnizzub toh a tlef I
.laro ta doog era sexof raeh I“
.naicitilop yna sa evitaklat sa tsomla dna
.spuorg fo tnelupo dna dekilsid tsom eht detegrat ecnanoS :er ,syad tsieh ym gnirud flesym ekil hcuM
.raey tsal ecrovid a ecnis
I…tsuj I ,gnihtyna od annog ton m’I .xaler ,xaleR“
,stnetnoc eht daer dna nepo epolevne eht deppir I ,nosaer eht revetahW
.esolc enohp eht dleh neht
?detseretni u :yddaDfloW_FTD
.edisni delemmup trihs rekcurt dialp a dna snaej ytrid ni raeb ylzzirg kcalb ,ffo dessip ,egral a dna
.noitazinagro tsivitkcah eht ot flesym evorp ot redro ni slevel gnidarged ot flesym no rab eht rewol ot deen t’ndid I gnitats yb nameltneg a gnieb tsuj erew eh fi ,rO .redneg yna sdrawot spihsnoitaler lauxes ro citnamor rof erac t’ndid I woh detcepsus ecnanoS :er fo tser eht ro simehT fi derednow em fo traP ”.ecA ,kcuL dooG
.syad nedlo eht ni ekil ,emirc a fo enecs eht ta drac straeh fo eca na evael ton dna boj a od ot gnimlehwrevo tlef ti ,eno roF
*** .eelg suoveihcsim ,lautum ni gnitarbelec erew ew ,revewoh ,nwod peeD
taht rebmun dedivorp a llac ot em detcurtsni txen redurtni-eb-dluow ym erehw
”?eurt s’ti fi em gniwohs dniM
.delkcuhc eturb eht hcihw ot ,delggig I ”,od lliw nexiV“ .eman a evig ot em gnitcepxe ,ffo deliart eH
.deugra I ”,deciffus evah dluow llac enohp elpmis A“
”!hctib diputs uoy ,elgnis erew uoy em dlot uoy—er’uoy os ,tiaW“ .lluks eninac kciht sih otni knas yllanif egnahcxe eht deraeppa ti ,nehT
.gnipsag fo tca elpmis eht ot ysatsce ni pil rewol ym tib dna kcab seye ym dellor I yaw eht morf ,laer lla saw ti thguoht eH
.saw redurtni eht gib woh tsuj
,enob a sa yrd sa saw yssup ym yhw gninoitseuq nigeb neve dluoc flow eht erofeB
.esruoc fo ,mus tsedom a rof—
,swodahs ’stnerap rieht morf suomonotua-imes ,emocni elbasopsid sseltimil yldrawtuo dneps ot devol ,citamsirahc ,yhtlaeW .seitirbelec fo sdnik esoht gnoma detnuoc yletinifed llahsraM
.pirt sih no yenom artxe dneps ot gnivah ta gnimuf tub ,dellab-eulb ylno ton llahsraM .rM tfel ew tbuod oN
tuoba yrrow ot deen t’ndluow eh ,ytilauxes ym fo snoicipsus evah did simehT fi nevE
.8102 ni ”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“ ,levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
.sgel sih neewteb gnitnet rexob eht gnittap yb mih detcartsid I
.tekcop nwo s’eninac emas eht fo tuo srallod dnasuoht-ytfif gnitrotxe ot su del ecnamrofrep gninniw-drawa
.eniuneg saw sregnif sih otni gnitaryg ym thguoht eH .laer erew snaom gnippiy dna senihw ym thguoht llahsraM nodroG .dnuom ym tsniaga dehsurb meht fo eno nehw gnihton did sregnif gnirednaw ,derucinam siH
.tsehc yrruf sih ot resolc su llup ot liat ym deldnahnam wap rehto ehT
.rae na dekcoc ’dnabsuh‘ yM
,noitnevnoc eht fo yad tsrif ehT
dluoc syad ym fo tser ehT
.ecalp fo tuo gnihton gniees ta deltsirb liat yM ”?olleH“
.ebirb eht tuoba detcilfnoc deraeppa eW
?snoitacilbuP namiL & llahsraM fo rotidE gnisivrepuS dna ,tnediserP eciV ,llahsraM nodroG fo draeh ev’uoy emussa I
’denruter‘ ti detnaw ohw rotatcid a ot tcafitra eht gnilles neht
?siht eldnah nac u kniht :yddaDfloW_FTD
.ruf der thgirb htiw nexiv a tub gnihtyna ekil kool flesym ekam ot dedeen I
,uoy ot dnuos 000,05$ seod woH“
.delworg eH ”!?siht si kcuf eht tahw ,ykciV“
.sehtolc emas eht gniraew
.nigiro eurt s’rellac eht dnif dna
”.nugdnah a ton s’tI
.pleh nac ohw maet a no eb ll’uoy uoy dnimer d’I thguoht llits I tub ,enif etiuq flesruoy eldnah nac uoy hguoht erawa era eW
na enola tel ,moor gninid evissam yllauqe na ot txen nehctik etinarg egral a ro ,eciffo renroc eno
.deb letoh dezis-gnik eht fo egde eht ot pu gnikcab erofeb ylsuorehcel dennirg neht
deen I dna ,em rof yad drah gnihctib a neeb s’tI“
dnalemoh reporp sti ot
.ffo ti deleep dna gnihtemos delbbircs eH
ot erised gnilwarc ,gnipeerc eht etaivella ro flesym retteb rehtie ot gniyrt tneps erew skeew ym ,syadawoN
.won skeew wef a rof tnemeriter ruoy gnihctaw neeb ev’eW .nedE .sM“
.sessalom ekil delbbub rethguaL .daer esaelP
.ppa pukooh ralupop eht no tnuocca nwo ym pu tes I dna
.neercsno dnuof eb ot langis eht rof gnieye llits ,dne rehto eht no deffocs I ”,ecnanoS :er fo draeh ev’I ,esruoc fO“
.sessik etanoissap ekaf dluoc I ”.xaler ot
.yrettol eht gninniw ykcul
,gnildnof deunitnoc I srexob detnet eht tub gnihton erow eH
.eborhtab sih deppord llahsraM nehw liat ym pu dna enips ym nwod tnew llihc dloc A
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tenretnI eht no snexiv citcra fo serutcip ruetama fo rebmun eht gnidnuotsa s'tI
trap eht deyalp htob yeht dna ,tuo denrut ti ,thgiwD saw eman s’raeb ehT
.emit gnol a ni tlef ton msaisuhtne dna noitapicitna rettu htiw hsiws liat ym edam tI
.kooBe na esahcrup syawla dluoc I
.nepo ti raet neht
,derumrum eh ”,suoegrog er’uoy ,kcuF“
.elttil a derettups regna eht dna ,detcennoc seye ruO
ev’dluow ylbaborp d’I
,pu ekops simehT ”,neht lausac gnieb er’ew woh gnieeS“
.sredloherahs emoselddem htiw ecnerefnoc oediv ruoh-xis a gnidnetta ni erusaelp lauxes leef dluow eh naht ereht nwod em gnisaet mih ni tseretni on tlef I ,hturt nI
s’thgiwD dna em ,emit emas eht ta tub ,erus ,flow dlo yzaels a no xes laro gnimrofrep otni derusserp neeb tsomla dah I
.mrowkoob gnihtemos-ytriht yhs ylbaroda na
.yaw eht ni selcatsbo suoires
”.yletal swen eht no draeh evah ton yam ro yam uoy puorg tsivitca-rekcah a fo redael dna rednuof eht
,tfihs reh retfa moor letoh a ot draug ytiruces naibsel eht gnirul retfa ysae neeb dah ti ot gnitteG
.ees ot eye eht sa raf sa sruf dna sepirts lla fo strevreP
,sliame lanosrep ruoy no tsap ruoy tuoba snoissucsid ruo gnivah etaicerppa dluow uoy kniht t’nod I“
was eh nehw retlaf ot flow eht rof ylno ,mih ecaf ot dnuora raeb eht gninrut deirt dna revo deppets llahsraM
,esrup ym ni dezzub egassem rehtonA
.ti nepo ot ton em dlot niarb ym fo edis decneirepxe dna lacinilc ehT
.doof sih fo setib neewteb delkcac oeL ”,ylreveB .srM
.og ot kcart erom on htiw tnemeticxe fo hgih A
.ffo ti devaw ylreveB .srM
sraey gnol net retfa pu tihs emos raet
.nosluaP ssiM tisiv ot dniheb deyats emos ,knird a barg ro lenap txen eht ot og ot tfel tsom elihW
.deredro d’eh telemo eht otni krof sih gud eh sa dehgis noil gnihtemos-ytriht eht ,nehT .ni denioj ylreveB .srM sa rethgual ni enam sih koohs oeL
.)ti dellac simehT sa
saw I noisulli eht ot del rehtruf sessalg dnuor emoS .emitremmus gnirud xof citcra na
.decnemmoc yllanif nalp eht ni owt traP .dekniw eH
.ppa gnigassem dedoc a hguorht simehT degassem neht
.senippilihP eht ni dnalsi na ot yaw eht lla dna aciremA htuoS ot nwod neht
.dlrow eht ni yenom eht lla htiw esoht ot ylisae emac moderoB  sicoV sumoD yb
.did stsivitkcah
.gnivomer derehtob reven fles tsap ym margorp erawtfos gnicart eht nar I ,retupmoc potksed ym ot enohptrams ym gnitcennoC
,epolevne eht hctans ot
did tahW“ .sdrow s’ruf a yb dedneffo erew yllaer uoy nehw tca eht depleh tI
,ssik evissessop rehtona otni em dellup eh ”,tniop dooG“
.rennid rof deredro evah ot doof hcihw gnisumeb detrats I ,tnemtrapa ym revo llef tesnus remmus eht emit eht yB
,tekcit yrettol gninniw a ekil kcehc eht dleh eh sa em ta kcab gnilims yllautum raeb kcalb eht ,su neewteb ecnelis esnet fo setunim ytnewt retfA
,thguob yletamitigel d’I sgnitniap dna
.llew hO .dengis meht teg dna skoob reh fo emos yub ot elbat eht ot enog
.revo erew snoitseuq ecno pu gnidnats ni esle enoyreve denioj I dna ,retal dnoces kciuq A
”straeH fo ecA ehT“   yojne esaelP
a otni denrut erofeb morf flow rebmit tnanimod-ecno eht ,kcab rewsna t’ndid raeb eht nehW
,rehtegot edaçaf ym dleh I ”,yob gib ,tuo dnif dna ees ot evah tsuj ll’uoY-
:yddaDfloW_FTD
.derised nem thgiarts
”…llew ,thgiR“ ”!lap ,tnemetatsrednu na s’tahT“
.lufrewop…gnileef em tfel ecneirepxe elohw eht ,revewoH
”,nemraC ,ti tuoba yrrow t’noD“ ”.araM
.ruf gniyerg eht htaeneb selcsum fo tes a delaever osla eh tub
.margorp eht gninnur detrats I sa desopmoc eciov ym tpek I ”,enif tsuj ,eniF“
.sriatspu pirt sih rof gnisu eb d’eh moor letoh eht ot em etivni dna tiab eht ekat d’eh ,nehT
.ti ni dnuof eb ot yrolg dna
.koobkcehc a dnif ot esacfeirb sih hguorht dereflip yldeirruh eH .pup hsittiks
***  .lairetam ecnanoS :er eb dluoc I fi ees ot ydaer erew eW
.puekam ym no krow ot thgiarts tnew I ,yltsaL
,elzzum sih tsniaga noows ot dedneterp I dna esolc em dleh eh sA
.nalp eht fo elor tnatropmi txen eht mrofrep dluow evitarepo dleif ecnanoS :er a
”…snoitanod eht ’evag‘ llahsraM .rM taht delaever eb ti evah ot ton ro rehtehw no hguoht nrot era thgiwD dna eM .esuba citsemod fo smitciv rof retlehs a si rehto eht dna ,htuoy QTBGL rof emoh puorg
.erocs tsal ym sa yenom emas eht gnisu ti thguob I
.elas taerg a ni tnedifnoc tnega etatse laer a fo elims gnitivni eht htiw em democlew llahsraM
,seires yrots naipotsyd yrruf gniogno sih sedulcni hcihw
.remmus siht emitemos noitacav a no gniog
”?dnasuoht ytfif eht htiw od ot nalp uoy od tahw :em lleT“
.thgin emas eht tcafitra eht gnilaets dna drac ecnaraelc ytiruces reh gnipiws neht
.dekcolnu rood tnorf eht deciton I nehw hguoht dnim ym fo kcab eht ot tnew renniD
,anueL yb uoy rof daer
,gniyas yb eman a delaever eh ,ecnedicnioc yb dna ,derewsna eciov eht ”,I od rehtieN“
”!?em no gnitaehc ylsuoires uoy erA“
Y“ ”.heh ,ereht nwod separd eht sehctam teprac eht epoh erus I“
”!ti enod neve t’nevah ew ,aedi gnorw eht tog uoy
”!nosluaP arreiS ssiM ,noipmahC s’noigeL fo leuqes eht ot rohtua gnimrahc dna lufituaeb eht ot uoy ecudortni ot ekil d’I“
.devaw dna elbat eht dniheb pu doots sserd remmus a ni knim ylbbub a sa deppalc moor gniteem demeht-oced tra s’letoh eht ni ydobyrevE
.sallertsE saL nwotnwod ni noitnevnoc koob a gnitisiv s’eh nehw flow dlo eht no part yenoh cissalc a mrofrep ot si noissim tnerruc ruO
”,ytiC nattahnaM ni seitirahc tiforp-non
,’simehT‘ sa em wonk thgim uoY“
,sicoV sumoD yb ”straeH fo ecA ehT“ saw sihT
*** .kcid tnetsixenon ym kcus nac serianoillib rehto eht lla dna tärksuM noeL ?ton yhW ?lleH eht tahW
?tnemeriter ni derob I saW
epolevne alinam a no llef seye rebma ym nehw yromem nwo ym gninoitseuq detrats I
rof yrotavresbO niffirG ot evird niaga ecno neht ,smuesum lacol eht neewteb gnippoh yad rehtona dneps ot dediced I ,hcnurb gniwolloF
dna gniludehcs s'noitnevnoc eht ta kool a yb dewollof ,stixe s’gnidliub eht otni hcraeser emos od ot dedeen ylpmis I
”.hguoht stop yenoh rof lufesu ylno m’I kniht
.moor eht ssorca em no seye s’flow railimaf a tlef I nehw saw noitnetta ym derutpac tahW
”.uoy detuocs ew yhw s’tahT“
?deneppah reve ,reve siht tegrof tsuj lla ew dna
?ebab kniht uoy od tahw
,tsop emas rieht ta erew keew suoiverp eht morf sediug eht neve ,raews I .degnahc esle gnihton elihw
.retal setunim thgie denruter dna lenap eht hguorht yawdim deraeppasid eH
.riahc eciffo eht fo rehtael enif eht otni gud slianregnif yM
ro snoitacilbuP namiL & llahsraM ot detcennoc eno eb ti rehtehw ,ot tnew I lenap revehcihW .ralupop ylevissam eb ot deraeppa noitnevnoc eht fo tser ehT
tuohtiw dna luftnevenu deniamer evah dluoc daeha keew gniusne dna thgin yM
.daor eht no desucof yawflah dna
.htaerb evitsuahxe na gnivig ,deksa yllanif I
.rehtruf em gnisirprus deunitnoc eciov ehT
”...bulc elttil ruoy gninoitnem devol dna esahp ’tsihcrana onhcet‘ a hguorht tnew syob neet ’srobhgien ym fo enO“
,smuesum s’niatirB taerG fo eno edisni ssalg evitcetorp dniheb decalp ksam labirt nacirfA na gnilaets no tes erew seye ym ,redlob dna regnuoY
evitarepo ecnanoS :er eht fi rednow ot detrats I ,dnim ym fo kcab eht ta dna ,rehto eht deporg dna dessik ew sa yb dekcit setunim ehT
,serutplucs kcank-kcink llams ,shpargotohp lareves ,stnetnoc kcabrepap sti
a uoy tnes[ :yddaDfloW_FTD
”?skeew wef a ni eraperp uoy naC
.owt trap ecnemmoc ot evitarepo ecnanoS :er eht gnigru etipsed gnilims
.hsid sih ot gninruter erofeb derekcins ,robhgien muinimodnoc wollef ruo ,oeL dna ylreveB .srM hcihw ot ,denoitnem I
”!dneirf a s’eh ,ekil skool ti tahw ton s’tI“
.anigav gnikael s’nexiv citcra na fo sotohp dnif ot enigne hcraes a no troffe hcum eriuqer neve t’ndid ti ,ylknarF
,yaweerf sallertsE saL suomafni eht otno emohrotom eht evord thgiwD sA .simehT fo
.yddig leef em edam tI
.efil rof em tes yllacitcarp boj tsal ym ecnis
.yltcaxe rebmemer
.kcehc dereffo eht ta ylsuoludercni derats ’dnabsuh‘ ym dna em htoB
yeht…erutinruf dna sehtolc ym sa llew sa ,enilno thguob I acilper a saw srotisiv dlot I siop stitep xua noegip eL eno eht
.suoicipsus mih ekam dluow gnillatserof taht em dednimer edis citsimissep yM .regnol tuo sgniht gard ot deugra edis lanoitar yM .rood eht tuo nur ot em dlot stcnitsni yM
.elbat nehctik s’VR eht ta yliddig dehgual eH
”?nedE .sM ,krow fo enil siht fo kniht uoy od tahw ,oS“
.moor letoh eht gnivael nopu gniggaw yllacitcarp erew sliat ruO
s’etaG nedloG .ereht revo si teb tseb ruoy ,nem htiw pu kooh reve ot tnaw uoy fI“ ,delkcuhc ylreveB .srM ”,eiteews ,sisaO dnemmocer I“
.htob su rof laicifeneb eb lliw sknar ruo ni tnemevlovni ruoy eveileb ylmrif I
.tsael eht yas ot ,slevon
.yraM ydoolB reh no deppis ehs sa deffocs ,em woleb thgir gnivil retto dega-elddim thgiewrevo eht ,ylreveB .srM
,hguoht ti etadpu ot erus ekam did I
etal fo sa rlwoH ekil sppa pukooh detneuqerf osla s'eH
.tnemeriter ni sseltser er’uoY
”?ew t’nod ,sevlesruo ot thgin lla-a evah eW“
.seye ym dellor I
”?tcerroc ,sesuoh noitcua dna smuesum ot og ot eunitnoc uoy teY“
,sallertsE saL ni emit a nopu ecnO
.erutuf eht rof srovaedne lairohtua reh ni kcul
.hteet ruoy neewteb ekans eugnot rieht gnittel
,sallertsE saL ni sletoh evisnepxe erom eht fo eno t’nsaw letoH ycnadnecsA ehT
,eliforp rlwoH eviterces sih fo eman eht em tnes simehT
tey yknal a ,emirc-ni-rentrap/dnabsuh sih dna raeb eht yb denwo eb ot deneppah os tsuj ti ,revewoH
.eurt-flah t’nsaw eh detacidni ecaf ym tub gnihtoN
,thguoht fo tnemom luferac a retfA
.maet wen ym edisgnola yllaicepse ,mrofrep ot spo dna sboj sseldne eht erutcip ydaerla dluoc I
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.retal setunim eerht nalp eht fo owt trap ecnemmoc dluow evitarepo ecnanoS :er ehT .ylesicerp 00:8 ta pukooh ruo rof llahsraM teem d’I dna noitom ni saw nalp eht mih dlot I
.’yenom wen‘ ot gniretac fo noitcnitsid eht dah ylniatrec ti tub
]otohp a tnes[ :yddaDfloW_FTD
.tesolc eht ni tsud gnitcelloc tnempiuqe dlo ym tuo gnillup
.tekcop eht ni tellaw sih fo tuo gnikop sllib rallod emos htiw ,roolf muelonil eht no gniyl raewrednu dna stnap sih dewohs otohp nekat ylitsah eht fo renroc A
.od ot tahw em detcurtsni simehT ,thgin lautneve eht rof snoitaraperp ym dna ynapmoc gnihsilbup maertsniam a ta rotide gnidael a sa seitud tnerrucer sih neewteB
fo gnikniht m’I“ .riahc ym ta liat ym gnihsiws yllausac ,deggurhs I ”,hcum toN“
.wohs rof t’nerew specib esoht
]otohp a tnes[ :nexiV_ydeeN
.simehT gnigassem erofeb iF-iW s’nnI ycnadnecsA eht morf enohp ym evomer ot erus edam I ,rebmun moor eht em gnidnes mih dna egassem tsal ym neewteB
”.ecnanoS :er fo rebmem a yllaiciffo er’uoY .nedE ssiM ,redro ni era snoitalutargnoC“
.tnemeriter otni gnol oot ton niart maets a ekil em tih noitalever tahT
.potpal ybraen a ta yawa gnipyt ecnerwaL ta kcab gnicnalg ,taes regnessap eht ni delkcuhc I ”,yay-ik eeppiY“
.potpal a morf dehsilpmocca eb nac sruo fo noitarepo yreve toN
”?ekil eb dluow erocs txen eht tahw gninigami er’uoy ekil erom smeeS“
.dehcuotnu deniamer
.yltnerappa ,llahsraM nodroG rof dias eb dluoc emaS
tog ohw nexiv der dlo-raey-eerht-ytrof elgnis a tsuj saw I ,wenk srobhgien ym sa raf sA
.naecO cificaP eht sdrawot denoitisop yltcefrep ynoclab koolrevo
.tnaruatser a ta sretiaw gnikrowdrah eht pit ot tellaw a ni hsac hguone gnivah ro ecnarusni lacidem ,llib retaw eht ,llib sag eht ,llib iF-iW eht ,llib cirtcele eht tuoba gniyrrow erom oN
”,ruf dna hself eht ni ro
?nosirp ot tnes dna thguac gnitteg fo sksir eht etavele syaw dlo ym ot gninruter diD .seY
.drawretfa ssenoil eht rof dab leef neve t’ndid I
,noitcif yrruf gnidaer/gnitirw elihw cisum evawropav ot gninetsil emit eerf sih sdneps ohw
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.naom laer a morf naom ekaf a tuo erugif enola tel ,boj reh od t’ndluoc ohw revol ysuol a neeb d’ehS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.cip kcid a gnidnes tuohtiw srohtua sih troppus neve t’nac godnroh gums ,suorehceL .hguone dias noitcerid lareneg ym ni spil gninnirg sih neewteb gninihs sgnaf yrovi ehT .yhw ylesicerp
,nekat enoN“ ”.oeL ,esneffo on
”?straeH fo ecA ,uoy dluoW“ .ezeerf em edam sdrow txen sih sa dias eh
.seires reh ni levon driht eht rof reliart koob tegdub-muidem a delaever ,snoitseuq derewsna ,koob reh tuoba deklat nosluaP ssiM
:tniop eht ot thgiarts teg ll’I“
.mrod sih fo edisni top fo tib ynit a sah eH ?tahw ,oS
.erutaerc-flah tenretni ruoy ,anueL yb daeR
.pil rewol ym tib I
.decart ylreporp eb t’ndluoc tbuod on
”.reffo na uoy ekam ot tnaw tsuj
.emit lanif eno em degassem eh
.boj lanif ym ot roirp sraey wef a neeb dah emirc a gnittimmoc fo tnetni eht htiw letoh a deretne I emit suoiverp ehT
,noitnetta ym thguac eerht ro tibihxe wen A .ruot rehtona
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,nnI ycnadnecsA eht edisni teg ot tekcit etunim-tsal a dekoob ydaerla d’I
.ytnelpa emac mih morf scip kcid eht ,scip tsaerb sselecaf emos mih tnes I tnemom eht ,yas ot efaS
.syawllah eht ni detagergnoc tsom elihw ,tranaf ni enilno gniees derebmemer yleugav
dna s’nosrep rehtona ot spil ruoy gnisserp naht erom gnihton tnaem yeht ,em oT
,ydob reppu ym revo lla ruf deyarg dna elzzum ym no sgnikram kcalb neht
.ruf sih htiw egalfuomac ot tnaem eborhtab kcalb hsival a gniraew ti derewsna eh dna ,moor letoh s’flow eht ot rood eht no dekconk I ,thgie erofeb etunim a toN
”.deriter ylekil dna ,tsieh gib taht retfa krad tnew ehS .dnuorgrednu tnew lerdnuocs eht wonk ll’uoy neht ,em tuoba smurof enilno dna srepap eht daer ev’uoy fI“
,sbro rebma larutan ym revoc ot stcatnoc eulb fo riap enO
nepo gnuws rood ehT ”—moor yna redro t’ndid I“ .ti denepo ylhsiloof dna rood eht ot demrots neht ,desolc ti deit ylsuoiruf dna dnuorg eht morf eborhtab sih deknay eH ”?kcuf eht tahW“ .noisufnoc detca rof yaw edam noisserpxe enipluv ym ni feiler eniuneg fo rekcilf A
tfahs eht ,llats moorhtab desolc a fo elddim eht ni tcere doots kcoc hsiflow siH
.oot ydaer saw eh em dlot simehT .ydaer tlef I
.trapa teef dnasuoht a naht ssel ylno eb dluow eW .noitacol ym ees mih gnittel dna llahsraM gnigassem neht ,noitnevnoc koob gib eht gnidnetta em devlovni nalp ehT
”,noitisop yksir a ni tup gnieb er’uoy erawa-llew m’I“ .dnah fo tuo tog sgniht erofeb retnuocne eht gnirud sgniht llats ot deen dluow I ,neht litnU
”.peels s’thgin doog ym tpecxe gnihtyna koot yeht raeppa t’nseoD .hguoht emoh ym otni ekorb ralgrub A“
,edirp htiw gnimaeb yawflah ,demialcorp leehw eht dniheb raeb ehT ”!ebab ,ereht boj dooG“ ”!eiteews ,ti did ’nikcuf eW“
,hA .slauxesomoh fo lluf
,langis eht evag I nehW
.nosrep eno naht erom ot degnoleb tI
eht ecivres dna nwod leenk ot em gnilangis ,sregnif sih ni erusserp erom elttil a tup llahsraM dna snoitpo ym dehgiew yltnelis I sA
,raey suoiverp eht tsuJ
.reh tius did reven tnemeriteR
naht gniticxe erom tlef gnihton ,noissim tsal desoppus ym ecnis sraey eht nI .did I ,eraperP
,dne s’lacisum gnizama na fo teiuq eht ot ralimis ,gnileef tug siht em evag emoh kcab gniklaW
evah t’ndid ylniatrec tI
.dnuora eb llits dluoc ni ekorb reveohw ,sulP
.gninioj eb dluow sih fo srohtua tahw dna noitacol eht gnisitrevda mih dewohs stnuocca aidem laicos s’llahsraM .rM ta ecnalg enO
,noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif osla nac uoY
.noos hcuot ni peek ot desimorp dna swap koohs ylmrif ew erofeb ton tub ,tnemtrapa ym morf skcolb owt ffo em deppord yehT
.neercs sih morf yawa gnikool tuohtiw ekops ecnerwaL
.part a eb syawla dluoc ti ezilaer uoy edam tug ruoy ni tcnitsni artxe na ,em ekil feiht nwonk-llew a eb ot desu uoy nehW
.doohdlihc ruoy morf eivom cipe na gniyalp sehsinif epat SHV eht nehw ro
”—efiw ruoy htiw gnipeels deirt I dessip er’uoy erugif I dna wonk t’ndid I ,kooL“ .moor letoh evitucexe eht ni mih gnihcaorppa ylzzirg eht morf yawa gnikcab ,thgirf ni pu swap sih dleh llahsraM ”!yeh ,yeh ,yeH“ ”.ssa
”?enilhcnup eht s’tahW
,ytissecen fo ,demotsucca eb ot si thgiarts naht rehto gnihtyna eb oT  .”letoH kcirevaM“
”,nedE .sM ,olleh…“ .’llac‘
.em revo gnitfaw aiglatson fo esnes a ot del meht ta gnikooL
?em ezingocer eh diD
.pu gnuh tsuj evah dluoc I
,edarahc eht htiw eunitnoc ot elbatrofmocnu oot leef uoy ro ,uoy rof raf oot seog eh tnemom ehT“
,ffo margorp eht nrut ot revo dehcaer I
.yruf ni depsag I
.E.L ni reywal doog A“
noitnevretni enivid
”?reh llac tsuj uoy
.stneve neewteb-ni eb ylekil dluow flow eht erehw
revetahw…gniod krow ot kcab tnew dna deggurhs yksuh eht hcihw ot ,desoporp thgiwD ”,tsael ta ,thgin eht rof ti no peels ot thguo eW“
,hcihw fo gnikaepS“
wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”straeH fo ecA ehT“
kcid siht tnaw u fi sriatspu moor a tog I :yddaDfloW_FTD krow @ ekyd a /w laed attog tsuJ .8 ta eerf mI :yddaDfloW_FTD ?letoh eht ni u :yddaDfloW_FTD ]otohp
,sboj neewteb ot nruter ot tnemtrapa na gnivah eunitnoc ot detnaw I fI
”.etaG nedloG ebyam ro sisaO neewteb deiT
”?yadot uoy era woH“
.eciov elam detrotsid a derewsna
”,noitnetta ruoy niag ot yaw tseb eht saw ti tub ,seigolopA“
”?tuoba siht si tahw…“
llirht si ereht
,sevlehskoob eht ,retupmoc potksed eht ,potpal eht ,sVT neercstalf eht morf ,gnihtyrevE