,elzzum sih no pu esae I
,em dna ekiM dna mih neewteb liev a ni setallitnics tsud etalucitrap sa
,buP dna raB s’nettibaelF fo edistuo teerts eht gnihctaw ma I
,”ned ruoy“ ssel neve eb ot ti tnaw t’nod uoy fi dnA“
.taews htiw dekaos si gnihtolc ym ,gnikohc m’I
.tib a rof swalc ym gnisu mih htiw ecnef I dna
.eye doog ym ni thgil eht dna
”.emit eht lla ereh emoc yeht ’nikniht elpoep tnaw t’nod I .pu yrruH“
,elims dna elims I
rettum mih ot netsil I
.hgiht sih fo kcab eht pu sedils swalc ym fo enO
”ecalP tsekraD ehT“
ni sllaf thgilnus ehT .ned
.sgge rieht yal ot dnim ym fo ecalp krad eht otni peerc taht sgniht eht lla yawa gnipmup fo dlohserht eht ta tsuj dna
.gnikahs ma I yrgna os ma I ”.tekcaj
.sniwt er’ew skniht syawla enoyrevE“
thgin ta yrd dna mraw em gnipeek si taht noitcurtsed derussa yllautum eht si sihT
.esseJ syaS ”,tihs hO“
,llew ,rellik laires yb snaem eh tahw rof sA
,ereht ni efil fo kraps eht rof kool I dna
.ydaerla elas sih edam s’eh taht
”.ereh era sdneirf gaf ruoY“
”.shtapohcysp tuoba semyhr etuc yna wonk t’nod I dnA
sgniht etarepsed od elpoep etarepsed
em ta gnilims ylleK ees I
niaga 8 saw I taht dna
.htob su swollaws taht wodahs kcalb a otni
dna ssarg dliw wolley eht dima gniredlom syal
,kciuq ti od t’nac I
ijustihoK yb ”ecalP tsekraD ehT“   …ecalp rekrad neve na
.tihs laer eht fo tsal ehT .lla fo tsal eht
.em ot sevlow ekil sdnuos ti dna
.hctapeye ym pat I
.pu kcuf eht tuhs tsuJ“
.ti fo erac sekat yxo eht
.eninac a ekil ,peed elahni
.tuo semoc gnihton dna ,semit eerht deirt ydaerla evah I .ssip
,gnikconk a s’erehT
,noognaR barc elats eht
.ffo kcuf ot mih gnillet gniredisnoc ma I dna
”.ereh nwod emoc dna ffo cisum ruoy nruT“
,taerht txen ym gniussi fo daetsnI
.ylregae stnahc eh
”.’taem ruoy tae retteb d’uoy
”.emit htnoillim-ruof eht reinnuf neve s’ti kniht I
,ekiM ta gnikool ydaerla s’eh tub
thgiarts si tihs siht ,thgir saw ylleK
.erehwyreve srekcilf liat sih dna
.ereh neve ton m’I ekil s’tI
.detrats I nehw etal oot ydaerla saw ti taht
ti hctaw I .maerd eht dna efil ym dna nwot eht dna thgin eht pu gnimmus
.mih sah htem ehT
.taht rof deen I tahw tog ydaerla ev’I tub ,yllacisyhp
.niav elttil a si ti fi neve
.sknits esuoh s’ylleK
,emit a nopu ecno ,dluoc I
.kcab sih tsniaga walc ym baj I dna
.sgnaf fo lluf elims a htiw sdrawkcab gnicnarp
,retnec sti nihtiw dlrow tnetsixe fo enoc ylenol eht ta
,sriatsnwod si daD
,gnihtemos yas ot htuom ym nepo I
.gnirewoprevo si reeb paehc dna ksum raeb fo llems ehT
.em no sllaf thgilnoom fo yar a dna
.dehcuot eb ot hsiw ton seod eH
.ti rof mih tneser t’nac I
.kcid a gnieb tsuj er’uoy woN“
tac gnilaed-htem yzzuks taht
.rae eno dniheb gnihctarcs
.tsaef s’rorepme na si sihT“
.mrots a pu gniggaw liat sih ,ekiM syaS
.noitingi sih snrut mih ni enimatehpmahtem ehT
,evatco na eciov ym rewol I
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR  .ytiniffaruF ta
.ereht gnidnats mih ees dna yawriats worran eht ot revo klats I nehT
.siht htiw gniog m’I erehw wonk t’nseod eH .drah m’I
?toiR nooM deR rebmemeR
.yhsiws elttil a sdnuos taht ti fo dne eht ot psar enilef yhctarcs
.’ytnur lla pu worg annog er’uoy‘ ,mih ot dias I“
.thgir ti od ,tnaligiv eB
,tuo gniog tekcar gib a ekam I fi taht gnikniht m’I
,ezeerf neht dna ,tnemom a rof
gnidliub eht fo edis eht otni sduht eh dna mih evohs I
”.od ot ereh er’ew tahw s’tI“
eno siht piks esaelp
.nus gnineve eht yb der d’olah leinaps hsilgnE na fo srae eht tuoba kniht I
?ti tuoba yas ot ereht si esle tahW“
.esnes gnikam sgniht teg ot noitatirri eht dna niap eht fo hguone tuo skcolb ti won tub
gniggoj tuoba kniht I
”.deciton uoy yppah os m’I“
leef em sekam taht dna
”?notnA thgir taht t’niA
,esseJ spsaG ”.ON“
.ti tuoba gnihtyna od nac I erofeb
,tol gnikrap eht ta emit tsal eno kool dna nrut I
.rehtaew remmus ni snaej yvaeh dna lennalf neerg krad gniraew m’I eveileb t’nac eh dna ,dik lesaew elttil ynniks a si esseJ
,uoy llet ot ereh m’I
siht sah ti hguoht
”…leahciM ta gnikool peek uoY ?tahw rO“
.gnilttar ytsan a s’ereht neht
.tsud emos swolb ,pu skcip dniw ehT
”?hsI ,uoy t’nera ,nam laer a s’eH
.doohrobhgien nwo ruoy edistuo tsuj eb llew yrev thgim ti tub
.maercs sih no elttil a sekohc eh dna
,niart a fo egassap lufnruom ehT
.deew-elcarim rof ecirp elbanosaer a s’tahT
”!od gnikcuf YLLAER ew seY“ ”?tekcor der
daeh sih snrut eH
.luferac ti od ot evah I os
”.deew slaed ylleK .edud oN“
.mih tpurroc ton lliw raewrednu dna
,em ot looc syawla saw eH“
.uoy rof niatnuoM ylenoL laer eht s’erehT
taews ni dettam lla
”?ereht ni gniog tsuj er’uoY“
krow sih fo erom daer nac uoY .neewollaH siht
”.sneppah tahw uoy llet ll’I“
:truh t’nseod ecaf yM
.lortnoc ni leef ton od I
”?ecnuo na rof hcum woH“
,kcihT .tuo dna edisni
.gniod s’eh tahw dna
tsal eht fo emos kcus tnaw syob uoY
,llaw a tsniaga pu mih gnihsup ,yas I
.deew siht ni seveileb ekiM
,tnemom a rof pots I
.dneirf ym otno dna
,mih ta nwod kool I
.ereh em detoor sah gnihtemos tub
.thgin eht otni ffo slerrab ylleK sa ezeehw dna liocer I
.tsap seog eh sa liat gnihsiws sih no ruf fo sliart gnirettulf eht ees
,ssenkrad lla dnoyeb
loop eiddik eht ni pets I
noisserpxe s’tac eht yb llet nac I dna
.strats dna spots ralugerri eht
.reveostahw ecaf rekop on htiw efil hguorht og ot mih desruc sah doG esuaceb
*** .llems-htem eht tuoba gnihton yas I
.sreweks feeb eht
,semitemos rebmemer ot drah ti edam taht dna
,yob notnA‘ dias syawla I“
.em morf yawa smriuqs eH
.senil rewop eht gnikahs dniw
,tuo teg ot seganam eH ”?…rO“
htuom mih leef nac I
.yad lla gnitae ekil tlef t’nevah I
.ti tuoba gnileef dab a evah I
,noitatnemal fo sesuoh eht ot yawa eeht raeb lliw I
yreve sekat tI
,eye ym mih wohs I
-drah dna gnol s’tI
”!HGAAAaaee—eem fo tuo eno dekcus LLITS eh dna deew rof elbuod yap mih edam I
.ezag deifirroh sih ni detcelfer ma
”.eyE sseldiL eht ot
.eciov a fo psar sih semoC ”?tahw rO“
,thginot ,nosrep hcus eno tuB .elbatrofmoc semoceb noitarepsed taht meht
,esseJ syaS ”.seY“ ”?thgie ekil
.tsud eht no wodahs tsegnol eht gnitsac
,relevart wollef ruoy
.mumixam eht ot deknarc nirg derussa-fles ykcoc sih
.gnimoc llip a evah I fi dna
.htuom sih ni taem emos htiw yad nevig-doG yreve dehsinif eh wonk lla’Y“
”!…evac a ni desiar ’niatnuom a ni nroB“
.ton seod eH ”.ebyaM“
,syas esseJ ”.edud tihs yloH“
.ti revo esolc nac walc s’taots eht erofeb yawa ti skculp tub
,thgilnus eht nI  ”?yekiM—
eh tub ,dam em ekam sgniht ynam oS .dam em sekam tI
,dnik sti fo tsal eht
tuo dellup neeb dah siri ym fi sa
.ega na fo dne ehT
ym hctarcs sa hcum os uoy fi rehtom ruoy ot oediv eht dnes
.revo nrut ti ees I
,ecalp rehtona seil ti dnoyeb
”,enisru enif ym xaleR“
rof ksa ton did I yregrus a rof diap eh oga skeew owt dna
dna sgab hsart eht rednu ereht sehcrep dna
,tib elttil a esir noisnet eht leef I
?wonk uoy ,’srenroc eht pu gnillif‘ ti llac yehT“ .ekiM syas ”,haeY“ ”.moor dnif ll’I .raeb a m’I“
.esseJ htiw pu speek ohw eno ylno eht si ekiM ,syad esehT
,si ti emit tahw rebmemer ot yrt I .struh daeh yM
.ehtaerb nac eh os pu esae I
.rab eht fo gnidis kcirb dloc eht ot drah mih gnisserp
,selcsum ym ni ehca-nrub tnatsnoc eht yojne ot em swolla
,slruc pecib ym no stigid elpirt eht otni gnippid
”.niarts tekcoR deR lanigiro eht fo sdees eht morf nworg saw
dna syart hsa fo noisseccus a ni
.eno laer eht no kconk nac eh os rood neercs eht yawa sllup dna ,ekiM syas ”,haeY“
”?gnikoms er’uoy taht s’tahW“ .yas I ”.oN“
”.looc s’eH .s’notnA fo yddub dlo na si sihT“
,flesym tcelloc I
.ti gnileef ma I dna ,yadot
.rekcurt a ro rellik laires a rehtie ekil sesserd hsI
.mih elgnad dna ffurcs eht yb mih hctac I
.dniw eht ni repat a
.kcab sih ot walc a tup I
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.nrut yht ni eeht yals ton lliw I“ .sinep sih fo tliw diccalf eht htiw yalp dna rae gnitiaw sih otni
.ereh ni lleh sa toh s’tI
,shtnom ni nekops ev’I naht erom si sihT
.gnivah m’I emit doog eht gnivah m’I ekil dnuos I
.niaga syas eH ”?tahW .rO“ ”.doireP
,ffo-ksum emos htiw flesym tih ,srae ym neewteb bmoc a nur I
,won ydob sih tsniaga ma I
.seertne eht revo hsiruolf s’namwohs a smrofrep eh dna elims kaew a mih evig I
,eye deniur ym ni thgis-non fo revils yrrulb eht hguorhT
.em ta pu walc a stniop eH
.emoh ta hcneb tuokrow ym no
,oga raey a fo sA
dnuorg eht rof eot a gnihcaer ,syas lesaew eht
.ti htiw gnola og tsomla I taht tsenrae dna layol os s’eh dna ,syas eH
.thgil yawllah egnaro fo anoroc a gniraew
.revol a ekil rae gnirettulf sih otni htuom I .mih hcuot I
.ekiM ta elims I
.enohp ym dna tellaw ym evah I erus ekam I
,ssip sih fo gnirettaps eht raeh I
.mih gninword neeb d’I ekil htaerb ni skcus eh dna
tnatsni na fo raems nedlog suoirolg eno otni sdnetxe thgin ehT
,gniloord ma I dna mih htiw hsulf ma I
,syug uoy era tahW
.mih retfa gnola gnippoh ,esseJ syaS
.niaga sgoj gnirps sih no og ot elba eb ll’eh mih sesimorp laicremmoc ygrella nA
.no deppets neeb t’ndah sgniht taht dna
,krad si ecalp siht hguoht taht revocsid lliw eH
”?ti seod ,raf llaf t’nseod elppA .nam ho naM“
ot desu os era yeht litnu
loop eiddik yrd a revo spoh eH
,ereht nwod dad ym s’taht tuB
.sezzaps fo elpuoc a ot lles annog s’ydoboN“
.seye ym esolc dna hgis I
,JM yknits fo lluf kcolpiz elttil a eerf sknay dna tsev ymirg
”.em pleh ll’taht ereh gnihtyna ekoms annog ton m’I
VT eht dniheb morf enil kcalb a swollof eye doog yM
redluohs ym otni hcnup lufyalp a spihw esseJ
,uoy ot gnihton naem dluow eman stI .ti ekil ynam era erehT
a ot revo sretnuas eH
tihs siht fo marg enO
.thgilnus eht ni gnivloser snrettap hctaw I
.em swollof gnileef maerd ehT .pu ekaw t’nod I
-hsI ,eye ruoy htiw pleh dluoc taht gnihtemos sah ylbaborp eH“
,thgim I hguoht yrt dna
.elbarenluv tsom si eh erehw tsniaga
,mih ot revo og leahciM ees I
,gnimoc s’eno on taht tcaf eht htiw spirg ot emoc ot yrt dna eye ym hctaw dna
.kcastun sih ta sllup swalc gnol ym fo eno sa sehcnilf eH
”.elbatrofmoc s’taht yaw on s’erehT“
,emarf rood ym ni niatnuom a ekil sdnats tsuj eH
wap ym tsniaga ”?KCUF eht tahW“
,leinaps hsilgne eht syaS ”.heh
etteragic til a fo llems eht tuoba kniht I
.sedis ym ta elgnad swalc ym tel dna
,deruoved eb llahs hself yht erehw
”?remmus eht gnirud taht raew uoy nac woh eduD“
,liat sih gniggaw ydaerla s’ohw
,bmot a fo bals eht ekil mih revo yats I dna
”?mih ot gnilles peek uoy
”.sdlo-raey-8 latnem nevE“ .yas I
.gnirps eht ni kcart rof tuo seog eh tub
.ekiM ta elims hsilef gnol a yb dewollof
yrcrtuo eninac eguh a saw erehT
”.pots ot sah eh dna kcid a gnieb s’eh mih llet ,hsI
?dneirfyob sih uoy erA
taews raef ekil sllems tI
.hcuoc cirbaf sih fo sniur eht ni kcab stis dna tnioj sih ta gard gnol a sekat ylleK
”.ffuts siht fo ESUACEB edam saw ASP dlo tahT
,ti otni peed kool mih evah I
.em ta kool ot dnuora nrut ot yrt ot snigeb eH
.munimula dna yorudroc fo draoh a no guamS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,rennid raeB yrgnuH a gnikam mih llems nac I dna
neppah ti gnihctaw ylno m’I ekil s’tI
esuoh s’ylleK erehw yella eht drawot ffo snrut dna kool a mih sevig ekiM .seye ym llor I
.sriats eht nwod pmots dna
,reeuq gnikoms-tnulb gnihcuot-liat egnarts taht ,rekcuf luof taht
”.tuoba yrrow ot evah ew ssa ynniks ruoy s’tI
.niaga hcneb tuokrow ym no tuo dessap I
?ecilop eht llet ll’uoY“
”.thginot pots annog er’uoY .thginoT“
.eugnot ym snekciht
eht tuo nur yeht sa ekahs sbmil yM
,su ot dlos eh nehw pu gnimoc tsuj saw eH .tuo dessilB .dlO
,sgniht selttes tI
,og I erofeb moor gnivil eht ni kool I
”.esseJ ,pots ot evah uoy dna kcid a gnieb er’uoY“
.sehcadaeh rof doog saw ti em llet dna yllom em lles dluow ohW“
.edistuo dniw eht ni epip a tsniaga gnilttar niahc a raeh nac I
.ytilibaiv-non otni tsomla derb sdees eht
,dnuora gnipmuj ecitcarp fo tol a sah eH
,enilanerda artxe
”.elttil a uoy tops dluoc I“ .sseug I
,yrreD fo traeh eht ni mih rof tsuj gninihs
”.hguoht em no yenom yna evah t’nod I“
ot deen a sa gnidareuqsam
.81 nrut I litnu
yenoh ekil ti eugnot I nehT
”.ydobyreve swonk edud eht
,ffo em dehsup evah thgim eh ,yliranidrO
dekan tfel eb dnim delevirhs yht dna
.mih hcuot tonnac elohtihs sihT
elttil eseht gnivah
.raeh ton od I skniht eh eciov a ni srepsihw eh ”,doG“
”?ssenisub klat ew elihw
”.wonk I ,edud hO“ ”.nam ,SECA
.skcub 002 ”.mih ekil tsuj kool uoy ,doG“
”.ydaer gnits a gnitteg er’ew kniht annog s’eH“ .syas eH ”.no emoC“
”.selur eht wonk uoY
ecaf ym ssorca walc a spihw dna
.doolb ym sliob etteuohlis yrev siH  .mih nmad
.gnitfil peek dna
.retaw fo gulg a htiw hctah eht nwod ti ssot dna llip rehtona barg I erofeb eno naelc a barg dna trihs tuokrow ym ffo ekat I
,cisum eht pu knarc
.won ytisnetni laer htiw gniniarts dna gnivohs
ti ta hcaer ot esseJ rof hguone yllausac ti sdloh eH
ti sa neve yrgnuh leef em stel
.lla ta gnihtyna nees gnivah tuoba flesym dna tsipareht ym ot eil lliw I ,retal sraeY
*** .steg eh rewsna ylno eht s’ti dna
evila nrub I .erats I .ehca I
.devivrus mlif eht wohemos tub
,hcum oot saw taeh ehT
,secuas tnereffid ni stib nekcihc deirf dna seldoon fo selip eht
”.emosewa sdnuos tahT“
.roolf eht fo elddim eht ni tfel neeb s’taht rehctip dia-look citsalp ytpme na revo sdap dna
”?huh ,em toohs annog uoY“ .looc s’tI
.hguot s’eH .mih ot ecnereffid a ekam t’nseod tahT“
.selkna sih woleb llef stnap sih taht erawa ylmid ma I dna
.secaf esoht fo eno evah tsuj I ,syas dad ym ekiL
”.…tub ,ecivda ym wollof t’ndid eh yas d’I
,sllorgge devaworcim eht ta tuo wap sih sdaerps eH
,meht dniheb rebmul I .ysmulc ooT
,dnuora gnikcuf ekiM dna esseJ tuoba ypmurg m’I
,amocualg naht erom no skrow tihs taht sselnu dnA“
,ti otni lrans enisru emos tup
.ruf etoyoc ni niar ekil mih fo ffo sehsaw nwotemoh ym fo htlif ehT
,ereh ni onrefni na si tI
.yas nac I gniht tseiracs eht fo kniht I .delddum dna
.ned ruoy ton s’tI
.derehtobnu reverof
.suomrone si ydob s’dad ,aksalA ni kcab rof nevE .eguh si eH
.nus remmus eht ni wolley ssarg eht hctaw ot wodahs eht ni tuo gnah dna eert mle dlo elttirb a fo edahs eht otni pets eW  ”.looc s’ylleK .trohs pu emac reven eh tub erus ekam ot elacs nehctik s’mom ruo gnirb ot desu eW .yna notnA htiw dekcuf reven eh dna
dilauqs sih fo edis eno enil sehtolc dedracsid fo seliP
”?edud ,sselekot yllatot nur tnecrep-llorgge siht od annog uoy era woH .pu tun
.ria eht ni smra sih gnileehw ,hcuorc-flah a morf em ta pu sgnirps esseJ
.erehwon fo traeh eht ni
”.pots annog er’uoY“
,esae sih yb detartsurf flesym dnif I
mih htob peek ot gniyrt ,elttil a evom I
.taob eht kcor ot tnaw t’nod I .won ydaets m’I
,won tniop eht sleef eH .enim fo ytsan
,kool yrros siht em sevig ekiM
,hcuoc sih kcab srehtils eh sa netsil I
.wodahs yreve ni peek I
*** .esuoh taht ni lleh sa toh s’tI .evael I
.tnemevap eht no kaerts gnol a sevael eenk sih morf doolb eht dna
,erus ekam ot tsuJ
,ijustihoK yb ”ecalP tsekraD ehT“ saw sihT
.semit lla ta htiw tuc ot gnihtemos tog s’eh rebmemer ot mih morf yub ohw sdik eht sekil eh sseug I dna
strihs-t gnidlom dna sexob tuo-ekat dlo fo srewot stI
”.haey haey ,sevarc eh lla sI“ .esseJ syaS
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”?teerts eht no tuo deelb em tel ll’uoy
,mih ot gniklat peek uoY“
”.sdlo-raey-8 ot slles eh fi peerc laer a si yug sihT“
dna prahs gnihtemoS
deirub si elbat eeffoc eht
”.pots ot gniog er’uoY“
.ti fo tuo neht dna
,emulp rehtona ,gard rehtonA
.tol gnikrap ytpme na dna
.no gnikcik lasopsid egabrag a ekil eciov a semoC ”,yoB“
uoy niatretne ot ytitne krad a yb dellepmoc si ohw ,ijustihoK yb
dna taews erusaelp dna
hsiw I dna ,niem ol yttihs tae ew dna
.egami gnittips sih era uoy ,yob tihS
.revo srewot regnol on eh
.erofeb siht enod reven evah I
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.etteragic sih fo ekoms eht etsat
htiw s’tahW“ .htribretfa na ekil mih fo tuo seussi elggig elttil ytsan a nehT .stnurg eh dna
.syot nwal deruocs-niar
.elims diletsum elttil ykeehc sih selims dna
.ti rof yvaeh oot dna gib oot nworg ev’I tub
.gnitalpmetnoc dna selkcunk yarg sih no tnioj sih gnippat
.drawretfa ssa ym no tuo eb ll’I tuB .niw ll’I
seye s’dad otni nwod erats I .siht etah I
yltaen dedlof hctap sti ,eno dab eht
.tfel ev’I taht kcehc ot pu teg t’now eh
.noitnetta gniyap ton er’uoy nehw lleh ot og yllaer sgnihT
sih edisni sehcaer eh dna ,tac eht syaS
,retaw otni gnillips kni ekil llems sih otni sehsaw raeF .lufrewop
.etteragic sih fo dne eht ta yrrehc gniwolg eht yb ecaf sih fo sliated eht ees nac I dna ,wodahs yfmoc
hcamots ym ni toob a stnalp tac dlo ehT
”?labinnac ymmug a otni niatpaC ehT nrut meht tel annog tsuj er’uoy dnA“
,swolb ot semoc ti fi swonk eH
”.emosewa si tI“ .syas eH
.hguorht peels ot gnihtemos sreloohcshgih nredom evig dna
,roolf eht ssorca sliart ti sa
,edud ebut ym ,sihT
,sdnilb eht hguorht srab tnebmal ,digir
”.uoy fo tuo pil erom yna raeh ot tnaw t’nod I neht
.puorg elttil ruo htiw gninnur tuoba kniht I dna
?ffuts siht tuoba ngiapmac elohw a dah yeht wonk uoy ,hsI“
.daeh sih sekahs ylleK
.ereh ni gnieb morf tsuj
.hguoht ,raew I lla s’tI
.psarg ym fo eerf gnilggirw yllufecarg dna
sega eht nwod emoc ot yltnailav delggurts dah tI
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.ylteiuq mih ot pu daert ot ecneitap fo ecnuo
,htgnerts enasni neddus htiw dna
.thginot mih ot gnilaed pots ot gniog er’uoY
,esufer ton dluoc tub
,drah nwod revel dna elzzum sih barg I
.srewol erutarepmet eht sa
.em naht reivaeh sdnuop derdnuh-eno lluf a sniamer eh hguoht
,s’dad ym ekil elttil a sdnuos eciov sih dna ,syas eH
.llits yrev seog eH .yas I
.doog os sllems siht tihs hO“
,arelcs eht fo driht thgir-rewol eht ssorca dehcterts syal taht dlog-lezah fo dnab driew eht
.evael ew dna pu yap esseJ dna ekiM
.lliw wen neddus siht ot tneidebo yletelpmoc
,mih htiw gnihgual si pup ehT
a depoleved sah eciov ym dna
?yawyna dik leahciM taht
,liat gniggaw eht pu
,huh ,em tug ll’uoY
ezag enilef neerg sih hctaw I dna
”.keew a rof ecaps ni uoy tup lliw
,seog eh sa spirt tac ehT
.niaga gnihtaerb trats
.toiR nooM deR rebmemer od I
”—esle enoemos htiw hcuot ni teg dluoc eh ,naem I“
.tsif evixelfer a ni delruc wap ym ,yas I
.egrof eht ni nori fo roloc eht
,ekiM ta gnikool s’eH
,lipup eht niatnoc regnol on nac taht siri demrofed eht
.rekcurt a ekil kool em ekam seod ti ,thgir s’esseJ
,god.ecioveht ta
.dehsawnu dna dlo si teprac ehT
.VT emityad fo anoroc eulb delgnim eht ni etteuohlis sih si llaw delenap-doow eht no pu dna
gnihtemos sallef uoy teg I naC
.sih no pu spih ym dnirg I sa
,em ni stis noitapicitna ehT
.esseJ dniheb eciov llams a syaS
erehw ,erehwyreve dnuof era secalp hcuS
,gnihgual tuo stsrub leahciM
,moor ym ni kcab m’I   .revo si dna
.mih tsniaga flesti stif gnihtemoS
,haeY“ ”.mih ekil tsuj kool uoy ,tihS“
.leahciM htiw gnicnad raw si esseJ daeha pU
.syob eganeet fo sessa eht ta gnol oot skool ohw
,eurt syawla saw tI
.rof em deen sdneirf ym revetahw htiw laed ot elba eb ot tnaw I dna
htiw seiggab golpiz ytpme dna nrocpop fo sgab
,em dellud ti tniop eno ta ebyaM .revo gnihtyreve
.trapa dellup gnitteg si kcol deggir-yrrej yM
,yawyna kcab emoc ot gnitrats si ehcadaeh ehT
ekil relliM fo snac esool
.flesmih ot muh dna
.ti fo tnecs eht htiw evila ma I dna
.seirrebnognil dna nomlas
.gniniarts era stnioj sih dna
.emoh kcab og I nehw krad raf eht ni dnats I
,yxo fo bat rehtona evah I
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT  yb uoy rof daer
.em ot tog eh detatirri yletaidemmi ,eltsirb I
.senut tuokrow eht ffo tuc dna walc a htiw xob moob ym bats I
dna elppa na ekil uoy eroc ll’yehT
.tsehc ym ni ylhsiraeb setanoser taht elkcuhc laitseb wol a htiw tuo semoc ti dna ,elbmur I
”.sedaced dna sedaced rof em epar dna tnemesab ruoy ni pu em eit ot ton esimorp uoy fi ylno tuB .tuo ti tuc ll’I
”!.…gnikcuf dna gnikcurT“
.stips tac dlo ehT
,tenalp eht no sraeb tseivaeh eht gnoma era eW
.elttil a meht ta lrans I os
dna ’kcuf‘ syas enoemos
,thgil pmalteerts etihW .thgiN
.ailager tilnoom lluf ni ma I
.ecalp a ,thginot tibihxe nO
”.ffuts taht yas ot ton dias I“
,gnihtaerb sih raeh I
.sneppah ti nehw ti ssim tsomla I
.yawa kool ot elbanu
.s07 eht ni ssuf a hcus edam taht eno ehT“
,eye dab ym dniheb ehcadaeh eht dnuora teknalb a ekil flesti gnipparw yxo eht leef I sa neve dna ,ereh ni ssip
.sdne kaerb remmus erofeb thgin eht seninac nwot eht ekiL
.esseJ ta kcab neht
,selpmas evig ot gniog ton er’uoy
.pu em gnizis ,tnelis s’eH
,evila s’eh ton ro rehtehw dna
,maet llabteksab eht no si esseJ
ma I tub dloh ym tsniaga gnilggurts s’eH
.heH ?ekiM ,thgir taht t’niA“
.seruzies ria-dim
,tac a fo eippih dlo tuo-gnurts a s’eH
,thgil fo loop eht dnuora eldis I
.ekorb daed m’I derebmemer evah dluohs eh fi sa
,erup reverof ,ekiM
,esaelp ,doG .mih nmad doG
.pu ekaw lliw I ,tnemom yna dna
.noitautcnup lanoisacco gnidivorp eudiser egnarts
.elzzum sih revo wap a spsalc eh dna
.won thgir ereh neve ton m’I
.yletal gnaf hcum mih gniwohs morf em spots taht nosaer emos rof dna
.ti nopu gnihca yal dna hcneb eht revo gnitnap nael
.gnikool-ykcits dna delknirc si gab eht dna
.ssenisub llA .syas eH ”.haeY“
,ecneirepxe sih fo mlaer eht tfel ev’eW
stfihs esuoh dlo ehT
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.suoretxed dna ynniks ,leinaps hsilgne na si leahciM
teef sih ot sehcrul ylleK
.secaf ruo ni enaj-yram gnilruc fo emulp a selahxe eh sa syas ylleK
--flesmih nam eht morf era sehctarcs eseht fo emoS
yliddig syaws eH
,eye ym otni erats I
.tlep kciht a tog s’eH“
.od syawla yeht nekcihc fo emag elttil diputs taht gniyalp ,gnola gniyalp
.hguoht gniltsirb morf em pots t’nseod tI
”.detalusni s’eH .retniw eht ni staoc yvaeh raew t’nseod eh emoc woh s’tI
.yllautneve syas eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,kcen sih fo ruf ytsum eht otni pu elzzum ym fo edis eht nur I .doog
”.koob gnicirp ym teg ot deen I ,tihs lleW“
”.trapa sraey er’ew tuB
.ereh ni lleh sa toh s’tI
.nokceb mih ees I
.gniloord ma I tub
.erehwyna gniog ton s’eH
.drocer taht taeb ot gnimia s’eh dna
”.retnepraC leahciM ot laed uoY“
.noitarepsed dnoyeb ees ot gniog si
,taht ni deifitsuj eb tsum eh kniht I
,skcitspohc sih htiw em ta sekop esseJ
,ylisae gniyaws llits liat sih ,ekiM syas ”,haeY“
.elpmas eerf a sa yawa nevig gnieb t’nia gnikoms m’I tahW“
,gnihtemos sah eh ebyaM
,liat eht no mih spahw sotiroD hcnar-looc fo gab ytpme nA
.walc eno htiw puos pord-gge ym ni snobbir eht rits I ***
dehtooms sah yxo eht won yb dna
ereh kcab erew enoyreve
,tuo ti dah I dna eh ,oga raey A .nworf I
,shtped deniur dna kcalb eht ees mih evah
.eye ym tuoba sksa eno oN
,hcaor sih ta skool ylleK
.xaler mih ees I neht dna
.efink a ro nug a rof ti ekatsim ll’eh ebyam
.taht tuoba od nac I gnihton s’ereht
.wonk uoy ,dnik sti fo tsal eht s’ti dnA“
.ffo srebmul dna snrut eH
”?ko ,trap ruoy od retteb syug uoy oS
,won kcab sih dniheb pu mra sih evah I
.epytoerets a pu yalp ot yaW“ .leahciM
I tnatsni gniteelf a roF
.yenom sih ekat ot gniog ton er’uoy
,siht ekil ,ereh em stnaw gnihtemoS
.repsihw I ”?tahw rO“
.taes-evol eht no em ediseb noitisop sih morf walc elgnis a htiw gnitniop ,esseJ syas
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,sriats eht fo pot eht ta gnidnats
.traeh ym hguorht rednuht ekil sessap ti dna
.remrahC eniuqE eht
syas dna riahc gnidlof sih morf pu sdnats ekiM .esseJ syaS
,enola regna ym fo taeh eht htiw yawa mih evird ot yrt dna
,kool a dneirf lesaew ym evig I
.siht tuoba evitcaorp eb ot denrael ev’I
,htaerb a yb denetaerht emalf eldnac fo etom a ekil gnireviuq
.ti revo teg t’nac I
.sllaw eht hguorht gnikaos spets yvaeh sih fo snoitarbiv eht raeh nac I
.yrreD hguorht sevom niart a ,yltnatsiD
,won esoht fo lla ma I
,notnA tuoba kniht I
.ylfeirb ,edistuo spets eH
staeb taht htrae siht no gnihton si erehT“
,mih ni noisnet ees I
,maebnus tnenamrep a ni delttes s’eh won tub
.gniliec eht ta tib a ni gnilruc ,llaw eht pu dna
.erutsop ym ro ecaf ym egnahc t’nod I tuB .yas I ”.ris seY“
,tcudorp hsup ot gniog ton er’uoY
,spuc maoforytS elyts plug-gib ecnuo-07
,ti fo tsal eht eb yam siht syas reilppus ym ,sdiK
”.…siht dna ,doof fo not a gnitteg dna pu gnikot
,ybab rekcurt ohcysp gib uoy ,eniF“
,revo eciwt nwot siht ni kcoc yreve dekcus rehtorb sih ,dneirf
”.pu kcuf eht tuhS“   ”?nug ruoy htiW“
.tuo gninnur si ria ehT .taeh gnimmiws
,tuo dessap I dna
.rorrim eht otni erats dna moor eht fo elddim eht ni tis I
.neppah t’nseod ti tub
.pu yrruh ot noitom a sevig dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.buc ,’niyas em tnaw uoy tahw tihs a evig t’nod I“
.ereht tog ti woh rednoW
.erom dna ,erom dna
,thginot ereh saw ohw eno eht si
retteb d’ohw ereh niatpaC eht s’ti tuB .lliw I“
.efil sih rof selbmarcs dna skcik eh
.laer si siht fo enon taht kniht tub pleh t’nac I dna
.noitasrevnoc gnirud tuo swalc sih speek eh eciton I
tnA ,em htiw ’nimoc dnim uoY“
.nwo sti fo psar tnasaelp
,ydaerla deruc dna tuC
.dik ,pu uoy kcuf dluow ohw elpoep wonk I“
”.sraeb-ymmug nialp em lles d’yeht rO
,tiuswal noitca-ssalc dna
,sllaw eht enil secalp doof-tsaf suoirav morf sgaB
89 s’tI .tsae gniog 36 yawhgih ot lellarap nur hcihw sliar eht gnola er’eW