,teef sih ot delbmarcs dah yrraH
”.niaga rehto hcae ta gnilley er’ew dna
,derepsihw yllaW ”.esaelP“
.remrahc eniuqe eht ,foohnorI mokaT yb uoy rof daer
,yrotciv ylno toN .ssol ruo tub
.remrahc eniuqe eht
regdab llat a fo erugif ehT
.haeY“ .detnurg yrraH
.desivda si noitercsid renetsiL
nam gnuoy a sa tnarongi oot
,thgif ew nehw nevE
.gniht uoy a eb
.tnaw ew woh evil ot ,klat ot elba gnieB
loots a no nwod tas dna rab eht otni ylwols deppets
.giws rehtona gnikat ,delbmum yllaW ”.dnab
,derepsihw yllaW ”.niaga nem nekorb owt tsuj er’ew
”.uoy naht erom enoemos evol dluoc I lleh ni ecnahc oN“
”!?siht ekil uoy era kcuf eht yhW !wO“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”.dlrow eht ni tihs citehtap tsom ,tsebmud eht
,retnuoc eht no nwod llits daeh
.yawa smelborp ruo kcufetah ro rab siht ni tis ot evah reven d’ew neht dna
.dnuora levart annaw d’uoy ,nwod elttes annaw d’I
.yawyna emac sraet eht tub
”dnuoW ehT dna tlaS ehT“
,yrolg eht dna rednow eht ylno toN .taefed tub
eht llits er’uoy
.dnahffo dias yllaW
.tuo thgir sniarb gnikcuf ym emac tsuj I taht
,flesmih dna yllaW no htob ,dah ti tceffe eht nehw
.riap eht ot dias namrebod ehT
”.rac wen a yub ot tnaw d’uoy ,yadiloh no og ot tnaw d’I
eno siht piks esaelp
”?em yonna ot dellepmoc leef uoy od yhW
.sessalg erom owT ”.em rof emaS“
.ssalg sih ta derats yrraH
.dewolleb yrraH ”!?em tuoba tahW
.eson-ot-eson tub lla riap ehT
?uoy etah I t’nac yhW“
,rehto hcae evol ew taht tpecca tsuj dluoc ew fi nevE
d’ohW“ .derettum yrraH
.derepsihw nooccar ehT
”.uoy detah I hsiw I“
ecaf sih no elims gnippird ,detsiwt a ,tew seyE
…tsuj revo gniugrA
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dna ,edirP yppaH
.uoy tuoba lla ti ekam t’nod uoy esuaceB“
.knird sih ot kcab neht
.era ew tahw fo trap era oot eseht
”.ssa ruoy tiuq annaw I .oN“
.tsicsaf a eb ot tuo denrut eniM“
taht denrut ew dnA“
.uoy gnisu ytliug os tlef I
.dedaelp nooccar ehT ”.em truH“
.ti rof reippah syawla er’yeht
”.eurt s’ti esuaC“
.niar eht ni morf emoh klaw ot evah I esuoh ruoy syawla s’tI
.roolf nedoow ymirg eht ot deppord ezag s’regdab ehT
attog s’ti kniht ot trats uoy elihw a retfA .gab gnihcnup
.mih ot retnuoc eht ssorca ti edils neht
.deil yrraH ”.t’nod uoy oN“
.ekil saw gnitcilfni saw eh yresim taht tahw tlef ylurt reven ohw elohssa nA
s'yrraH dna sih koot namrab ehT
…tuo demrots ev’I retfa elohssa yehca na htiw
”?gnol taht gniog neeb ew evah doG ?sredro tsaL“
”?stunaep emos tnaw uoY“
”.hcae fo tekcap a teg s’tel ,hcae rallod a ylno er’yehT“
dna em emalb dna em tih ot
,eniw fo ssalg rehtona deruop eH
truh ’nikcuf os leef ot detnaw reveN
eniw der eerf-lohocla fo ssalg dereffo eht koot eH .deretlaf neht
.yrt neve I semitemoS
;yltfos deksa yrraH
.rab eht pu gnikcol detrats dna
”.nobruob rof thgin enif a si tI“
thgir em detaert s’ohw dekcuf ev’I nam ylno
.ksed eht no sregnif sih deppat eH
.rab eht fo srenroc rehto otni
”.tnaw uoy tahw s’ti wonk I hguoht nevE
”.rekcufrehtom taht retspmuD“
”.truh ti ekam dna taorht eht yb em barg ot uoy si tnaw yllaer I tahw nehW
.flesmih rof ssalg rehtona deruop neht
”.gnivah s’eh tahW“ .dehgis neht
ot dah I .tuo mih kcik dluoc I erofeb em morf yenom elots eH
,ti morf deniard eniw eht sA .knard dna
,deilper yllaW ”?nam wen tahW“
,tsal ta dias yllaW
”.tluaf ym s’gnihtyreve em llet dna
”.em truh ’nikcuf yeht enoemos evol dna yrt I emit yrevE“
.tsil yrecorg a revo gniugrA“
.eniw eht fo pis rehtona gnivah ,dias regdab ehT
.ylluftsiw ylrettu ,deilper yllaW ”.ti
”.lap ,leef uoy woh wonk I“
thgin eno rof stsal evol taht tpeccA
.detpurretni yrraH
.ssalg eht dellif diuqil eht sa detnurg eH
”?leef taht seod woh
.ylsselmia detalucitseg nooccar ehT
”?nam wen ruoy s’woH“
esuaC‘ ?taht rebmemer ,emit eno stnim fo tekcap a revo deugra eW“ .detrons eH
stunaep em gnidnah speek efil ,si elbuorT
.rednetrab eht rof derutseg yllaW
”.won kcid retteb gnikat s’eH
,em tih ot gniyrt speek
,doG“ .deerga yllaW dna ti llifer ot dereffo namrebod ehT
.lufraF lacsaP yb
.trapa tfird ot gniyrt tpek hcihw
.maerd taht ni uoy htiw syawla m’I dnA
,detrats yrraH ”-c I eruS“
”.pu em elir ot em ot gniyl tsuj era yllaer uoy woN“
.derongi eb ot desufer sresuort sih ni ssenffits eht
.detnurg yrraH ”.uoY“
.delbmur dna ssalg sih denwod yrraH
”.si ti yaw eht tsuj s’taht dna kcuf dna thgif ot nrob erew eW
”!?ti tnaw uoY !eniF“
,keew eht fo yad rehto yreve nehT
”.ti ot detcidda m’I dna
,skcub owt dah I setunim 01 nihtiw dna
lufraF lacsaP yb ”dnuoW ehT dna
.ssalg eht morf gniggiws ,delbmurg yllaW
ecno rof lortnoc ni eb ot
!uoy tuoba lla ti ekam ot evah uoy woh etah I“
.knird nwo sih ot kcab dekool yrraH
tnimreppep detnaw I fi ediced t’ndluoc I
,yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
’ninevE“ .elbissop sa yllaW morf yawa raf sa
erahs ot deb a dna dneirfyob a
.tuo deklaw eh dna
.dratsab dlo na sa rettib oot dna
,delrans eH ”.truh I
.deppis dna ssalg sih delriws yrraH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
seceip llams owt otni dekcarc d’ti woh gnicitoN
uoy truh I nehw retsnom gnikcuf a ekil
”.yaw emas eht sdne syawla tI
.ezag sih tem
lla fo duorp eb tsum ew dnA
.derettum nooccar ehT
.elihw a rof ti htiw tas dna
.pis a gnivah erofeb
.nam a ekil leef em sekam
”.gniyrc uoy ees dna
rehto hcae gnikcufetaH“
,thgil hself a ekil em esu uoy yaw eht tuoba ’nihtemoS“
”.sklof sredro tsaL“
”?sessalg ynam woH“
.niaga ebuc eci taht ta gnirats ,loots eht no depoord yllaW
”.drowefas doog a hcus saw
.ytpme erew ssalg dna regdab htob litnu
.deksa regdab ehT
.esuba rentrap etamitni fo meht sdnimer dnif yam srenetsil emos snoitautis dna
,evol ruo ylno toN .era ew taht
”.tihsllub taht rof derit ooT“
.smaerd s’elpoep pu ’nikcuf peek
”dnuoW ehT dna tlaS ehT“ saw sihT    ”.sseug I ,haeY“
”?em detah uoy thguoht I“
.dnab rab a ni deyalp dna seivom orehrepus dekil eniM“ ”.oot em ,haeY“
.elbat eht no tsif sih gnimmals ,deppans regdab ehT
.eugnot sih dloh t’nac ohw htuomduol tnagorra ,bmud a m’I
.nam a ot taht did ecneirepxe
ti htrow si kaerbtraeh eht oS
”.riaffa na evah tsuj
tlah a ot dnuorg ebirtaid s'yrraH
drah gnikcuf os s’ti yhw s’taht dna
.rewols tsurht uoy gniyrc trats I emit yreve
”?eergasid I t’nac yhW“
.siht detnaw reven I“
,trohs deppots yrlevar s’yllaW
,enoemos htiw xes evah I emit yrevE“
…dna semoc gninrom eht neht dnA“
.nekopsnu yal sdrow eht fo tser eht gnittel erofeb
.ti evresed t’nseod ohw hctib a fo nos ylno eht er’uoY .uoy truh ot
.knurd sekatsim gnikam ekil t’nod I“
.ti ni gnitaolf ebuc eci elttil eht ta derats eH
”.gniyrc trats ll’I ro gniknird pots attog I
.segap ytiniffAruF dna
…oerets eht revo ,VT eht revo
”.yaw gnikcuf emas eht sdne syawla sihT“
”.elohssa elttil dehcterw uoy ,uoy kcuF“
yas dna eye eht ni em erats ot uoy tnaw I dnA .eromyna
.ezag eht teem ot tpmetta on gnikam
,duol oot s’ohw yug emoS
.maerd a s’ti wonk I woh s’tahT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.dehgis yllaW ”.ti eb d’tahT .peY“
.dewolleb yrraH
”.rac sih latot dna esuoh sih ot erif tes athguo I“ .delworg yllaW
yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.em truh ot uoy tnaw tsuj I
”.ti naem ot hcum oot uoy evol I
.deksa namrab ehT
doog os sleef ti esuaceb
.ylmrif dias yllaW ”.efil ruoy pu kcuf uoy nehw seilf emiT
,yrraH ta ecnalg a elots yllaW
,pu gniraet morf peek ot deppots nooccar
”…rof thgin enif a si tI“
,hcuot I enoyrevE
.em morf laets dna em ot eil ,em truh
,tnaw uoy tahw tog uoy
.nobruob eht tuo deruop dna yrraH fo tnorf ni ssalg eht decalp namrebod ehT .t’ndluoc dnA
,srenetsil erutam rof
.elohssa na ees I ,rorrim eht ni flesym ta kool I revenehW“
ria eht fo tuo taerter ot demees ekoms ehT
.seye s’regdab eht otni ylgnidaelp ,gnirats
”?lausU .yrraH
.em tih ot uoy rof deggeb dna
.dehctiwt eson s’nooccar eht dna
,dik a sa naem oot saw eH
”.oot uoy detah I hsiw I“
,ton ro pu mih gnidniw tsuj saw yllaW rehtehw fo sseldrageR
”uoy evol I“ wenk ohW“
.ssalg sih ot kcab denrut nooccar ehT ”.uoy tpeC‘“
.skeehc sih nwod ruop ot nageb sraeT
”?tnaw uoy fi hctam gnimaercs eht ot piks dluoc eW“
.sselnoitom doots yrraH
.detsisni nooccar ehT ”.od I“
”.doog on em od t’now ti wonk I tuB
,dnuorg eht ot uoy gninnip
”.stunaep gnitae m’I elihw em ekohc t’nac uoY .od nehT“
,mih morf deniard regna
”.gnineppah gnikcuf pots d’siht neht esuaC
”.em rof gnimoc speek taht retsnom adnik eht emoceb annaw t’nod I dna
seye ruoy otni kool ot ylnO“ .dehgis eh dna
-dna roolf eht ot yllaW enilsehtolc ot ydaer tuoba
.shpmuirt rof kool ot si
eybdoog yas reven dna
.ynroh er’ew nehw doog sleef ylno gnithgif eht dnA“
semoc gninrom eht
sllaw tsniaga em gnivohs
gninrom eht ni em no tuo klaw neht
,devlovni ”deen“ taht tahw gniwonk ,tcejbo ot devom yrraH
enoemos tnaw tsuj I dnA
.ti ot desu gnitteg yllanif enoemos
.deksa namrebod ehT
,haN“ .derepsihw yrraH
”.emoh kcab tekcit sub a dna evol ot ydobon
”.emit eht lla maerd I“
.si ti wonk I tub ,tluaf ym t’nsaw ti em gnillet tpek yeht
.uoy no gnittips dna uoy gniniur
.tsal ta ssalg ytpme sih nwod tes yllaW .sknird erom owT
elzzum eht dnuora drah os em dekcams dna wap ruoy gnuws uoy yllanif neht dnA
.uoy truh ylurt t’nac I
.pis rehtona koot regdab ehT
”.melborp ’nikcuf eht m’I tahT
.nac uoy ekil em truh ro em kcuf nac ydobon tuB
nooccar ehT .yllaW ta yldliw gnitalucitseg ,teef sih ot tog dah regdab ehT
”.od I tub t’ndid I hsiw I“
.stresed tsuj sih tog reven ohw elohssa na ees I
”.oot rebos mih deen I ,owT“
.troser tsal fo noitome na sa dehgual yllaW
.ma I uoy htiw evol ni erom eht
deggeb I emit eht rebmemer I“
”.stnim revO .thgif a otni
”.od uoy taht enigami I fi em rof reisae tsuj s’tI
”?kcuf ot woh no eerga ylno ew nac yhW“
leef I .taorht ruoy gnizeeuqs m’I nehw retteb leef I taht etah I
ot dah I neht dnA
”.thginot ezoob erom on knird annaw t’ndid I dias I nehw ti tnaem I“
.ssalg sih dehsinif dna delbmur yllaW
sevol eh nam eht nehw ti setah ohw
.napdaed yletelpmoc derettu yllaW ”.uoy t’nia ti taht eciton ylno I
.nooccar eht ta revo kool t'ndid regdab ehT
.detnurg nooccar ehT
”.tner ekam ot tsuj kcab syad wef a rennid piks
,retteb gnitteg ti ,gninniw evoL
.mottob eht ta elddup llams a otni detlem dah sebuc eci detarapes owt ehT
”.efil ym ni drah nmaddog os emac reveN
,loots sih no kcab tas dna elttob eniw eht dehctans eH .mih no denwad
”.yllaW ,derit os m’I“.ssalg
”.dnem t’nac taht evol a htiw nem nekorb owt tsuj er’ew
.deppots regdab ehT
.deksa yllaW ”?meht ro em
.ti od t’nac I tuB“
,ssalg llams a otni lohocla lezah eht ruop gnoht rehtael eht ni namrebod eht dehctaw eH
?meht tae tsuj uoy t’naC“
.ylreporp ti od dna yrt ew nehw nekorb steg taht traeh ruoy syawla s’tI
ehT”.seye nmad ruoy ni niap eht ees dna
,ti tnaw uoy em llet uoy hcum woh rettam oN
.sdne ti woh wonk uoY“
ygolohtna noitcif yrruf lacirotsih gninniw-drawa eht ni yrots a sah eH
ecnaddir gnikcuf dooG“
,xes hguor fo noissucsid sa llew sa
.detnurg yllaW ”.esruc ruo s’taht esuaceB“
traeh sih ekorb I nehT“
.flesmih fo lluf oot ,tnagorra oot
yllaW dniheb denepo rood ehT
,ti ot derettum eH
.ti terger ot nosaer dah yeht hguoht sa
,em taert uoy esrow eht dna
tsal eht naht erom struh kcuf yreve wonk I esuaceb
,sgniht gnorw eht gniyas peek I
teem I nam rehto yreve neht tuB“
.yawa gninnur peek evol I elpoep eht dnA
.sresuort sih no gniworg erp fo niats yvaeh a dna
.delbmurg nooccar ehT
,edirP fo seirots rof gnikool ni ,tcnitsni tsrif ruO
.rehtael fo tlems gnihtyrevE
,rennid revo tsuj s’ti nehw tuB .ti deen ew nehW
rettam tcejbus tluda sniatnoc yrots s’yadoT
”.tnaw uoy fi yrc nac uoY“
,em evol ot uoy tnaw t’nod I
.loots eht no ylhguor nwod kcab tas regdab ehT
yug fo dnik eht er'uoy dna
.gninrom eht ni evael tsuj t’nac I“
evresed I dna tluaf ym lla s’ti ekiL“
tuo seye ruoy gniyrc ,ereht tas er’uoy nehW“
.tam eht no drah nwod ssalg sih tup regdab ehT ”.dluoc I hsiW“
war elohssa ym kcuf uoy elihw
.ykaerc erew staes eht llA
,gnibrutsid yllaitnetop evoba eht fo yna dnif uoy fI
,skcub owt htiw tuo detrats I“
.niaga teef sih ot mih werd elbmar s’yrraH
.llaw eht ta derats yllaW
:revewoh ,desahpnu demees namrebod ehT
.uoy truh ot em gniksa peek uoY“
”.rof geb uoy niap eht fo yna evresed uoy taht si em dlot ev’uoy eil ylno ehT
.tuoba er’ew tahw si
evol ew syug dnif htob ot su tnaw I“ dias regdab ehT
.rehtie owt eseht htiw moor eht ni eb ot tnaw t’ndid tI
.yllanif dettimda yllaW ”.niaga ti tnaw I“
wap ruoy htiw ruoy htiw sdne tI“
sevol eh nam eht ta stunaep skcilf ohw
a sa em sees ereh dnuora nam yag yreve ekil s’tI“ .delworg yrraH
.gnitalfed ,derettum regdab ehT ”.oN“
.sciborea od ot sevitceted rumel siocebeuQ rof sesucxe gnidnif yltnatsnoc si siht fo edistuo dna
,edis eht ot tuo shtoob eht ni gnikcuf erew yeht tcaf eht edih ot gniyrt tpek syuG
”.od ew thgin a roF“ .detsetorp yrraH
uoy ta kool evah reven I
.pihsnoitaler yppah taht ,emoh yhtlaeh taht fo maerD“
,yawa klaw yeht nehw esuaceb si ti taht wonk I
,gnibbos ereht eil uoy nehw
.niaga ssalg sih ta dekool nooccar ehT
.swap sih ni daeh sih tup yrraH
.mih ta stunaep skcilf
.evael tsuj t’nac I
yug fo dnik eht m’I esuaceB“
deb ni si nam ym doog woh tuoba garb dna tekramrepus eht ni uoy dnif annaw I .elsia kcab eht ni nam ym gnikcuf rof gniddew ruoy fo tuo dekcik teg annaw I
.emit dnoces a yrc mih ees ot evah t’ndid yrraH os
.daeh sih gnisiar ,elims ot detrats nooccar ehT
”.riaffa na evah dluoc I kniht t’nod I taht tsuj s’tI
”.egnar gnikcilf ni
”-dias uoy dna tnimraeps fo
,loots taht fo ffo uoy gniggut tsuj yfitsuj nac I ylisae erom eht ,ereh tis I regnol ehT“
”.laeh t’nod ew tuB“ ”.laeh em tel
.pu doots dna
.hctib a s’efil esuaceB“ .dednamed yrraH
,no ’nitaehc eb uoy
uoy deen t’nod I woh dna
,elpoep gnitruh peek I“ .dettimda yllaW
,taorht ym gnizeeuqs
.hcnul rof og ot erehw revo gniugrA
”?I t’ndid ,uoy htiw evol ni llaf gnikcuf
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
.thgit seye sih desolc regdab ehT
”.meht yfitsuj tsomla naC
spil sih ot ssalg eht thguorb yrraH
.ylduoL .dehgis eH
.taht tpecca tsuj dluoc I hsiw I gnihtyna fI
,em dnuora truh erew elpoeP
.taht rof nwod eb d’ohw syug dnif t’ndluoc ew kniht t’nod I taht neve ton s’tI“
.ecalp dlo eht hguorht detfaw ekomS
”?yllaW ,lausu ruoy tnaw uoY“
.niaga namrab eht nwod gniggalf
”.hctib a fo nos A-edarG a era uoy kniht od yllaer I dnA .uoy roF ,em roF
.detrats ew erehw ot kcab er’ew …neht tuB“
”.gnihtyna eerf lohocla rehtona em teG“
.yrraH ta tunaep a werht neht
eveels sih ot daeh sih desserp yllaW
uoy gnittis speek dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,enola meht gniyrrac naht retteb si meht gnirahs esuaceb ot gnilc ew esoht dna noitarepsed dna worros tuB
oot dehgis yllaW "?kcuf annaW" derettu eh nehT
,tnaw I tahw teg I
.delrans yllaW
”.melborp ym eb ot uoy tnaw I“
gnuoY saW dlroW eht nehW
tlaS ehT“   :osla tub
”.era uoy nam eht eciwt s’nam yM .elohssa uoy
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY   .emit rehtona
,yllaW ta revo ylwols dekool eH
.uoy ekil nam a fo kcerw emos no tuo ti gnikat no ffo teg d’I taht
.yrraH htiw seye gnikcol yllanif dna gninrut erofeb
,uoy morf yawa klaw I emit yreve woh etah I dna thgif ew woh etah I“
.uoy fo gnimaerd pots t’nac I
wol depoord daeh sih