,bulC eht morf gnihtaerb erauqs ruoy rebmemer uoy oD
.delbmert seenk dna kcals tnew sredluohs ym
.tah pot reh devomer dna riahc reh morf esor egam ehT ".tseug
.erofeb did ehs sa wap reh delruc neht ,walc a pu dleh ssenoil ehT
keehc ym tsniaga dehsurb gniw ehT
,em erofeb gnidlofnu enecs eht neewteb htrof dna kcab erif-dipar decnuob sthguoht ym ,emit taht nI .ruoh
.mossolb sutol a ekil dnim ym ni dedlofnu sdrow reH  2 fo
.dnim ruoy daer nac I os
nac eht ta detniop neR
,ylregae pal ot nageb ynnub ehT
.dellortnoc gnieb erew stnemevom sih fi sa
.sdnih ym ot dereggats I sa em morf dils neR dna neleH ".traeh
,elahxe yvaeh a htiw ,nehT
.ydaer tlef I nehw hcuot ni kcab teg I taht ylno gniksa
.ecitnerppa ym ecaf ot nrut
.niahmaS retfa sthgin eerhT
si gnidleihs ruoy gnorts woh wonk t'nod I—ecneirepxe ll'uoy tahw uoy llet t'nac I
.redluohs ym no wap a tlef I litnu ,niaga dna niaga
,flesruoy rof tser eht revocsid ot evah ot gniog er'uoY .trap a ylno tub
.sdniM gniriuqnI ,dezigrene saw I
.em fo tuo sdrow eht teg ot thgif ot dah I ekil
.lleps cigam a tsac tsuj I
.meht gnitsiwt dna sregnif yldnips ym gnilruc
.daeh ym edisni sevlesmeht delaever
.eton nettirw a dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
!noitamrofsnart fo serif eht dna xineohP eht nopu llac I"
,tniop siht ta devieced neeb d'I gnirevocsid htiw epoc d'I woh wonk t'ndid ylurt I
thgir saw eciov s'neleH
.tilps sparts arb ym sa citsale fo pans eht yb dewollof
.gnireffo ruoy eveirteR"
.ni-kcehc rehtona tuohtiw od ll'I lla s'taht uoy llet nac I tub—
.detsisrep ,revewoh ,elims deye-yssalg siH
.elbarenluv ro kaew em llaC .elbissopmi
.dehcaorppa I sa delims neR dna neleH
,sdniM gniriuqnI ,ti ebircsed ot esle woh wonk t'nod I
.maet sdael yriuqnI eht liame esaelp ,enuejeL enitsuJ fo stuobaerehw eht ot sa noitamrofni sah enoyna
stsaerb reh desaeler neleH
.hcuot rieht htaeneb toh gninrub
.hceercs dehctip-hgih a raeh ot ylno esirprus fo yrc a tuo tel I
.neppah cigam eht tel ot ssengnilliw A
.evol fo dna ,noissap fo
"!desimorp uoy tub—
.tlef evah ot dah
.moc tod rettiwT fo yletal ,etoyoC triD yb daeR yb uoy rof daer ,ynnuB oK dna
.roolf eht otno ylsuoinomerecnu nac eht deppord neht
,niaga em ot swap reh tuo dleh ehs erofeb oediv eht ot gnidrocca setunim eerht ylno saw tI
enod d'yeht tahw fo esuaceb dnA .deveileb
,pots ot hsiw uoy nehW
.aremac dnoces ym nettogrof d'I taht tfel d'I retfa dezilaer ylno I
.gnillac ym wollof dna boj ym peek t'nac I
,nepo won si ,ffo desolc gnol
,truh eht rof pu ekam t'nseod tahT
.ruf s'tibbar eht ni sngised eht morf gnimoc thgil eht ot ralimis
,mih dniheb doots neleH
.sregnif tsellams ym ta dna stnioj eht ta gnilgnit
mih fo tnorf ni nwod tlenk ehS
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,elzzum ym edisni kcil a kcoc s'neR evag ,seye ym desolc I
.reh tel ot desufer I esuaceb ,ecudorp ot deliaf ehs fi tluaf ym saw ti naem dluow lasufeR
.mriuqs reh ekam ot reh hcuot ot erehw tsuj wenk eH
.snolat wen reh fo ssenprahs eht htiw selppin reh desaet dna stsaerb reh deldarc ehs elihw reh edisni gnilzzun
,kcen ym fo epan eht no htaerb reh ,rae ym ni
.tseug ruo eraperP"
.secneirepxe dna sevil reeuq fo yticitnehtua eht fo slained dna ,eerf era ohw esoht fo ysuolaej leuf seod dna nac tnemtneser detesolc taht deined eb tonnac ti tub—gniht eno rof
.nialpxe dluoc I gnihtyna naht erom siht detnaw I
...taht deneppah tsuj dah gnihtemoS
",knird eht rebmemeR"
,erusaelp ni naom mih ot gninetsil dna ylwols mih gnikcus ,nwod dna pu bob ot nageb I
,ti detsiwt I woh rettam on
,nosinu ni ekops neR dna neleH "!raos ot
.dnuorg eht ta nwod dekool neht ,detatiseh ehS ".ecneirepxe
,hcrop eht no doots I
.esle enoemos ot neppah ti gnihctaw htiw evil ot evah neht dna
,deddon dna denaorg I
"?gniod er'uoy tahw em llet t'nac uoy fi ecneicsnoc doog ni eerga I nac woH"
,prahs dna gnol ,snolat emoceb
",uoy evigrof I" .em degnahc tI
,elcric eht dnuora esiwkcolc klaw ot nageb yeht ylwols dna
.flesym no taht thguorb I tub
.rehto yna ekil tsuj
.aremac eht etipsed elbaplap saw
.retne uoy erofeb gnihtolc ruoy fo emos dehs ot hsiw thgim uoY"
.noitseuq riaf a s'tahT" .deddon neleH
.sedis dna smra ym neewteb gnituorps
.gnidaer-dnim ekil elpmis t'nsi sihT"
.drah oot yaw dellup I
"?taht ekil uoy dluoW"
.reh dniheb dekcut sgniw wen reh
.roolf eht no tops a gnitanimulli ,blub elgnis a
sa ebircsed ylno nac I taht ecarg a htiw pu flesreh detfil nohpyrg demrof-ylwen ehT .gnitiaw
.nwod wols ot ksa ot neve pots ot tnaw t'ndid I
,dias ehs tahw gniyned ni tniop on s'erehT
,niaga llac siht dnetxe eW
,uoy eripsni taeh eht teL
.llet dluoc I yaw yna ni degnahc dah ti tuoba gnihton yletulosbA
.yawa seye ym raet t'ndluoc I .dewollaws I ".neppah
fo tros emos llits saw siht esac ni tsuj no arb dna raewrednu ym tpek I .tub
.tiuq uoy ,deliaf ti nehW
.nac eht sdrawot delias I sa em deirrah—sgniw ym—
.laog dne eht reven erew sgniw ehT"
.hcuot sih ta delbmert ydob elohw reh dna
.em hguorht elppir llits ecneirepxe ym fo skcohsretfa eht ,retal skeew owT
,erusaelp fo gnireffo siht ekaT"
em ot denrut neR
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.bulC eht fo srebmem eht neve
.em nihtiw erusaelp fo hsur eht kcab dloh t'ndluoc I litnu gnol t'nsaw tI
,desreveR sdrowS fo thgiE ,desreveR ratS
.eromyna taht od t'nac I
.ymmut dna tsehc ym sserac ot nageb tibbar eht dna ,deddon dna
,em gniydaets snolat reh
,meht tuoba enoyna dlot reve d'I kniht t'nod I
.detsiwt dekool ti
tuB" ,tuo derettups I
;srevol eht ta depag I
,cigam eht ot ydob dna dnim ruoy gninepo ,gnixaler
,taht rof pu ekam lliw yas I gnihtoN .yrros os ma I"
,erofeb did ehs sa swap ym tuo dleh I ".od I ,seY"
,rae ym ni saw eciov s'neleH ".ereh
,taht ...ecnatpecca dnA
.nosinu ni doof eht sdrawot denrut dna erew yeht erehw kcab elcric lluf a ,deppots yehT ".raos
eno siht piks esaelp
.ecnis tnacav doots sah dna
tsirw s'neleH morf gninnur thgil fo enil a
.deilper segam eht
.ebordraw ruoy no ysae eb yltcaxe ton yam sihT"
;delbmert eciov 'ssenoil ehT ".drah
.gnitaralihxe saw tI
.em otni mih koot dna
,drawrof yltcerid klaW
,kaeps ot elzzum ym denepo I
.ereh krow detrats I ecnis elpoep ynam os morf ,noitasnes taht
.enim fo tuo swap reh dekrej ehS ".tiuq
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.neR did sa ,noihsuc eht otno drawrof deppets neleH ".erusaelp fo
.deraperp si gnireffo ehT"
.dnuora yletelpmoc denrut d'I litnu
.tnatsid dna yssalg seye sih ,em ta dekool eH
,kcalb tsepeed eht erew srehtaef reH
.enarbmem niht eht tsniaga gnihsurb tsuj swalc s'neleH fo kcab eht ees ot kcab decnalg I
.egdod a sa nees eb dluow on ro sey a tub gnihtynA
.ytinrete nwo rieht erew taht sdnoces net ro evif esohT
,yltnesba kcen sih dekorts ehS
.did I ".od I tub—tub
recarT "yrerrO" anitsirK yb
gnireffo wen a htiw
,sdleihs ruoy tsap uoy xaoc ot dedeen I wenk I dna
.nwo ym ylbainednu saw
,nepo ti dekcarc I sa dessih tI
,gib oot tlef eugnot yM "?thgir
noisserppo
ym hguorht gniraes tub xes ym ni ton
deriuqca ylgnimees dah yeht egdelwonk lanosrep ,etavirp tahw—
.uoy sediug ti sa erif s'xineohP eht fo erusaelp dna htmraw eht leeF .hsiw uoy sa erolpxE"
,em fo tnorf ni saw ti ereh ,woN
.niaga ssenoil eht ees ot gnitcepxe
,ekops yeht yaw eht
,uoy fo trap emos kniht I"
.thgil nedlog fo selcric dewolg spitregnif dna ,tsirw ,woble eht fo sedisni eht no
.elcric eht fo egde eht sdrawot gnihtemos hsup ot demees yeht
.did I ,tnemom taht ta dna ,saw I tuB
".meht htiw eltneg eB"
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,lleps eht denoitnem d'I
.deksa nohpyrg eht
,tuO .ruof ,eerht ,owt
,debborht em dnuora dlrow ehT
delddarts ssenoil remrof ehT .deddon dna
,ydaer era uoy nehW
.kcab yal neleH sa drawrof denael neR dna
.ni worg tsrif yeht nehw evitisnes er'yehT"
.siht tnaw ot tnaw t'ndid I
,sdniM gniriuqnI
,ylthgils sdrawkcab daeh reh dekcoc nohpyrg ehT ".retne
.ecneirepxe lauxes esnetni erom hcum a snaem tahT
”ytnuoC moctahW fo hctiW ehT“
.swap ruoy ni meht dloh dna
,tsehc dna kcen reh nwod deruop emalf ehT
,tep reh ta nwod dekool ehS
,noisicerp egnarts htiw deklaw eH ".esaelp
,ria eht ta yltnelis deggut ehS
,won noil dna drib fo xim a
,bulC eht ta sdneirf ekam ot gniyrt detsaw d'I emit eht ta saw I yrgna woH
em fo tnorf ni yleerf delgnad kcoc siH
.L ot degnoleb ecno gnivah sa esuoh eht wohs sdrocer
.tiaw dna ,kcab petS
ti was I nehw s'taht dna
,lleps eht tsac dluow ew dias I"
.ylteiuq deksa nohpyrg eht
.thgil fo gnir eht fo tuo
.dnatsrednu I .seY —I"
.taeh eht hguorht lennahc a devrac yrc esraoh s'neleH
,edirP yppaH
.nwo ym tsniaga sserp ot eugnot sih gnitivni
,redduhs dna eslup ot demees dlrow ehT
.yleerf nevig eb tsum ti
,yletaidemmi evitceffE
.rehto eht drawot dehctertstuo mra eno
.deniamer tab eht fo tnih oN
yleritne eb lliw tniop taht dnoyeb
.raos thgim uoy taht
.yawyna reffo taht dnetxe ot detnaw dna
noitisop ym ni flesruoy tuP .tlef taht woh
,ni htaerb peed a htiW
em tsniaga desserp shgiht s'neleH ,retal tnemom A
.lleps eht rof nosaer eht reven tub
,nac gnihton ;sseldrager
.em sdrawot denoitom dna esor neR ".retsigaM
.detaeper I ",ti tnaw I"
demrof taht eulb tnecsediri htiw derettaps
,enips reh fo htgnel eht nwod delevart ti emit sihT
riahc eht ediseb seenk sih ot knus neR ,did ehs sa
.meht dexelf ehs sa gnihctaw yltnatsnoc demees taht seye
.yriuqnI morf ngiser I
,psag a draeh I sriatspu dna
,elgnairt eht ni doof eht ecalP
.tfel ehs erofeb ksed ym no rehtaef s'worc
.ésopxe siht rof lavorppa lanif reh teg ot adisserC .sM deliame I
.raos dluoc uoy taht ylno
.tibbar eht ssik ot ni denael dna
;gnilliw naht erom eb ot evah uoy ,ti tnaw uoy fI
daetsni saw enitsuJ
.htuoy ym fo seisatnaf eht fo yromem emos
,gnirepsihw raeh ot nageb I
,em ni esool gnihtemos nekahs dah
.sraey ni noisses s'tsipareht tsrif ym deludehcs ev'I dna
,kcoc dna swap s'tibbar eht
.erifpmac a retfa slaoc eht morf stfaw taht tnecs fo dnik eht
,recarT ”yrerrO“ anitsirK yb
.noitcerid ym ni detrad dna nepo deppans seye s'neleH tub
.gnitsiwt setunim owt elohw eht tneps
.seenk ym dnuora loop cirbaf kcils-lasuora eht gnittel
ylevixelfer dna
,sey ,taht ytilibissop eht tsael ta tpecca ot dah I—
,gnosgnis yhtaerb a saw eciov siH "?retsigaM ,seY"
.xes ym edisni edils hself naht remraw gnihtemos tlef I delahxe ylprahs ehs sa neht dna
,cigam taht yaw rehtonA
,tnapicitrap evitca
,gnissap erew kcohs fo sraet ehT ".sey
,koot yeht mrof tahw rettam t'ndid tI
.trofmoc ruoy ta yleritne s'taht tub
.erac t'ndid I tub
,gab eht ffo pu doots ehS .ylhtraenu
.noitidnocerp a seined reven yriuqnI
,dees ykoms sih htiw elzzum ym dellif neR ,naorg a htiW
.thgilf fo tfig eht rof ydaerla ecno tuo dellac evah eW .ecalp siht ni
,pit eht ta devruc dna daorb ,kaeb a neht dna
.em dnetta ,ecitnerppA"
.ssenkrad eht ni gnirekcilf dna gninetsilg ,seye s'neleH nihtiw til erif larutannu nA
,detrap elzum siH
.meht esaet ot nageb dna stsaerb reh ot swap reh thguorb neleH
.flesym ot eurt eb ot tnaw I fi ereh gnikrow peek t'nac I
.meht fo tol eht ,sduarf dna sreveileB eurT
.drawretfa yletaidemmi demuser neleH
htiw werg taht htmraw fo liart a tfel hcuot riehT
deddon I yletuM "?enitsuJ
,dloH .ruof ,eerht ,owt
.rae reh fo egde eht gnola ylthgil hteet tnorf sih dezarg eh dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.su fo eerht eht neewteb naom dna tsurht yreve
,dehtolc ylluf neve
.em dniheb rood eht desolc dna edistuo em derehsu neht ,dewob eH ".ni
gnirac ton tuoba nepo os erew yeht yaw eht
.wap eno reh dereffo I .dias I
,yriuqnI htiw emit ym lla nI
.ettenoiram detfarc yltrepxe na fo ecarg diuqil eht htiw noihsuc eht ffo dellor neR
.kcab ym tfel snolat reh dna
.snosaer thgir eht rof gniht thgir eht od uoy taht seriuqer tI
.ereh lortnoc ni era uoY"
.rehto hcae gniveileb etipsed
evah ton thgim I
deppord sdnah riehT ".em
,krow rieht deunitnoc neht snolat reH
hctiW ehT“   yojne esaelP
,liamkcalb ro knarp etarobale
.ezag ym tem swap enipluv elpmiS
"?meht peek I od woH
.sredluohs ym ta llits erew snolat reh hguoht
.em eb ot ti tnaw I
.gab repap eht deppord dna ados dna ydnac eht debbarg I
,noisulli eht rettahs
;ecarg dnamed nac eno-oN
.deddon dna niaga
.sduarf erew deweivretni d'I elpoep eht deveileb syawla I .neppah ot siht
,niaga gnos-gnis ywolliw
ssensuoethgir-fles yM
.nialpxe t'ndluoc I taht
,I dna neR ,rehto hcae htiw ssergnoc ni tlenk eW
.nrecnoc fo kool a htiw dedlof sgniw dna smra
.ti timrep uoy sselnu
ecitcarp lautirips xodohtronu dna
.tnemom eht ni tsol
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,ydob ym hguorht nar redduhs A
.elcric eht fo retnec eht edistuo tsuj gnittis s'ttibseN fo
,sredluohs dna elzzum ym dna
,loohcs hgih retfA ".uoy eveileb I"
.hturt lanosrep fo stiusrup 'srehto no boj tih tsal ym neeb evah lliw sihT
.niaga maerd taht gnicneirepxe fo yhtrow leef ot gniog reve m'I fi dlrow eht ot kcab epoh taht evig ot evah I
.kcalb hctip ot denepo rood eht dna ,retal spar prahs eerhT
.rae ym elbbin dnA"
.moor eht otni daeh sih kcuts neR neht dna ,reduol werg gnipmuht ehT
uoy llet ylno nac I
,ydaer era uoy nehW
;niaga taes reh koot dna deddon neleH ".flesym
,neR fo seye eht otni thgiarts dekool I daetsnI
;ti was I taht neht saw tI
neeb evah reven thgim I—
emoceb evah I taht
.egelloc ni bulC eht fo seiromem dna
,tenalpruF ta esahcrup rof elbaliava ,slevon dehsilbup owt sah ohw
laever ot ruf rieht dehs sevlesmeht swap eht erofeb
.feileb seriuqer cigaM
.tneserp dna desucof
"?ecaps emos deen uoy oD
,dezilaer I ,ecnarT
na ekil tlef ti tub
.did ehs tub ,wenk ehs tahw wenk ehs woh wonk t'nod I
,deppots s'neleH sa noos sa pu dekcip neR ".tfig
.daeh reh koohs dna wap eno pu dleh ehS ".tub ,seY"
noitatiseh s'tnemom a tuohtiw dna
,noisiver tuohtiw elcitra eht devorppa neleH
.tnemom taht ni dehsinav noitasnes eht tub
,em deveileb ydobon nehw saw I truh woH
.erew yeht pu-kcuts woh
,gnisir shgiht ym neewteb peed taeh eht
,tnemom a rof tsuj ,enigami ot yrT
,ti evig ot ton esoohc uoy fI
.gnikrow a deirt dna
,roolf eht otno deppird ruf ym nopu tfel yeht ssem ehT
.ylduol oot ti yas erad t'ndid I
aka noilykciN dna
dluow ti fi derednow I
,rotidE roineS ,noshpesoJ .M—
.tcartnoc lla-llet a rednu weivretni na fo elddim eht ni gninraw tuohtiw yletelpmoc emoc dah ti dna
,spil reh ssorca derehtag srekcilf llams esohT
.ti lliw uoy sselnu
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
,seitnap ym nwod deggut ehS .deddon dna
.llats ot deirt I
.em edisni peed msaps toh gnihtemos tlef I dna
,repeed wohemos tey
taht ni eciov s'neR saw tI ".thgil
.elcric eht sdrawot edorts I ,elzzum ym fo edisni eht gnikciL
.ytiniffaruF no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,krow dehsilbup tsrif s’oK si ytnuoC moctahW fo hctiW .ytiniffaruF no revo ybboh a sa setirw ohw ,ynnuB oK
,taht yaw a ni tnaem ti tahw yltcaxe em dlot taht noitacinummoc a
ediw smra reh dleh dna
;ssenkrad eht morf tuo dehcaer mra nA
,aremac gnissim eht htiw gnola
",su ot flesruoy denepo uoY" "?...woH" .did ti
,ti evah ot sah enoyreve kniht I taht tpecxe
,emalfa saw em fo trap yrevE
.seenk sih no swap sih htiw daeh sih dewob dna
na eb ot uoy deen ot gniog m'I ,ybxiB emalB"
.noitarepsed dna noitacilppus ni seenk ym ot deppord I sa em gniteffub ria toh fo hsur a
noihsuc tfos egral a detanimulli seldnac ehT
,neppah t'ndluoc ti flesym gnillet fo sraey net retfA
,gnireffo eht pu dekcip I nehw repparw eht dekcehc I ".elcric
.stsehc rieht ot swap rieht desserp htob yeht
luac ruoy tsap uoy xaoc ot yrt I elihw rae ym no elbbin dna sredluohs ym bur ot neR tnaw I taht uoy llet nac I
.tnatsni saw tcapmi s'drow ehT ".ecitnerppA"
.kcab sih denethgiarts dna htaerb prahs a ni werd neR
.noitseuq eht fo tuo saw
.pohskrow eht eraperp ot gniog m'I"
;repsihw hsrah a ni tuo emac drow tsal ehT ".laer er'yehT"
.dnuorgkcab eht ni derepsihw neleH
,gnignahc saw ydob reH
.ti dnif t'nac enihcaM kcabyaW ehT
.denruhc hcamots yM
,od I yhw wonk t'nod I"
.sdniM gniriuqnI ,ti
.nruter ni ytaorht dna wol
,tfos erew sdrow s'neleH ".tep
,rehtegot ti dnib ot ni nworht rettub tunaep fo tib a htiw
.srae reh fo esab eht ta spooh deroloc-reppoc llams eht dehcuot hteet sih emit yreve deredduhs pitliat reH
.tsap dekcit eno tsal eht sa feiler htiw gniggas ,duol tuo sdnoces eht detnuoc I
,sedis ym ta deggut niap yratnemom A .sedis dna smra
,elcric eht fo egde eht ot deppets I
.krad eht otni ,dlohserht eht ssorca kcab deppets neht
.htaerb prahs a ni werd I ".tiaW"
.degagne saw I ".em
.neleH hctiw detroprup eht morf noitativni na detpecca
.kcab ym nopu snolat reh gnikrow neleH htiw
.uoy segnahc taht tnemom fo dnik eht s'tI
,enoyna eb ot gniog s'ti fI
.siht evah ton t'nac I .siht tnaw I"
fI[  .ybxiB emalB .reveileB eurT a
,em ediseb nwod tlenk dna daeh reh koohs neleH
sgniw yrehtael wen owt eht ta derats dna seye ym denepo I
,ksum ykoms tsomla ,yhtrae na erob tfahs siH
em dniheb nohpyrg eht fo taeh eht leef dluoc I
"!srehto fo straeh eht nepo thgim I taht
.truh ruoy egdelwonkca tsael ta nac I tub
,repsihw neila emas taht
,s'neleH did oot os
.uoy ssik ot ekil dluow teppup ym kniht I"
,snoitartsinim sih nageb tibbar ehT
.hcrop eht otno yltcerid
,oga sraey neetfif desolcerof saw ti ;ybxiB
.elzzum sih tsniaga xes reh sserp ot sgel reh gnidaerps ,tsiaw s'neR
.noihsuc eht evoba esor dna smra dehctertstuo rieht morf depmuj taeh dna thgil fo evaw A
ycamitni fo sreyal dna
,neppah lliw gnihtoN"
rewop eht rekees siht tnarg ti htiw dna
”ytnuoC moctahW fo hctiW ehT“
regnil hcihw stceffe ynA
,yriuqnI enizagam lacitpeks-cigam eht morf retirw a
,neleH etisoppo doots eH
.ti dias ehs nehw gnibbos detrats I taht dna
.elzzum ym otni ti dednepu neht
.yaw eht srehto wohs ot won su pleH"
.woble sih dehcnelc I nehw tcaer neve t'ndid eH
.rethgirb werg thgil eht dna
"—noitamrofsnart fo semalf eht fo repeek ,xineohP"
,ni htaerb peed a koot ehS
.taht gnizingocer rof uoy knahT"
.sraet ym hguorht yltneg emac sdrow s'neleH ".yrros m'I"
,esahcrup ’skcirt s'yriuqnI fo yna deined taht ecafrus htooms-latsyrc a ,trohs ni ,saw tI
.erofeb sa tsuj ,delaes llits saw ti tub
.degagne eb ot tog ev'uoy
I dna tew tlef skeehc yM
.sllafdnih fo rettap dipar eht yb dewollof
,rehtegot sdnah dleh htoB
esolc siht teg ot gniog ton m'I"
htaerb peed a ekaT
,elzzum ym otni ados eht fo tsal eht delbbird I sa psag dekohc a tuo tel I
.tfig ruoy rof uoy knaht ew—"
.drow eht htiw flesym dekcohs I ".oN"
.kcirp thgil yreve htiw deredduhs ssenoil eht dna
.revresbo na tsuj ton
htaerb peed a koot I ".ti
.raos oot thgim yeht taht ,degnahc eb dna gnireffo rieht fo tae meht tel
.noissefnoc a evah I ,sdniM gniriuqnI
"—rof tuo pets em teL"
,deneppah dah tahw retfA
sgniw ym—sgniw yM
.emas eht od uoy pleh ot gniog m'I fi flesym fo erom tsefinam ot deen ll'I
.wap eno htiw meht ta depiw
.dnas eht ni enil ym eb ,neht ,siht teL
.nwod sdap thgir ,pu sdap tfel
,dessap erif eht erehW
.decamirg neleH "?ti od uoy naC"
,mih ot enim denepo I dna
,noihsuc eht fo egde eht ta dekan dna deggel-ssorc tas neR .ti lliw ot demees neleH sa kcals ro tuat
,eno yb eno ,moor eht dnuorA
.gniworg em fo tnorf ni tibbar eht dna
recarT "yrerrO" anitsirK yb
,erusaelp fo tfig siht uoy reffo eW
.saw I thguoht I tub—
,pu kcab tas dna reh morf yawa dellup eH .neR did sa
,sdniM gniriuqnI ,tug yM
,ti ekil gnihtemos ro
ylurt yeht esuaceb
.rohpatem lanoitcnuf a sa pu enil
?tcepxe uoy did tahw lacisyhpatem a
.dne lliw lautir eht dna ,egareveb eht knird
.lautir eht retfa ylkciuq dedne weivretni ehT ".od
.seye ym erofeb thgir
.noitseuq sseldrow ni em dniheb llirt gnisir s'nohpyrg eht draeh dna dnabtsiaw ym ta gut a tlef I
.sdniM gniriuqnI ,eveileb ot tahw uoy llet t'nac I
”ytnuoC moctahW fo
.neR fo tnorf ni noihsuc eht otno nwod knus I
.ecaps eht ni tuo gnignir eciov reh ,ekops nohpyrg edam-ylwen ehT
kcab s'neleH gnola dellor swalc s'neR woH
.elcric a yb debircsmucric ,elgnairt a ees lliw uoy dnuorg eht nO" .tnanoser erom
.rood eht ot emoC
.ni uoy tel lliw I dna semit eerht kconK
"—tub ,neR no uoy wohs ot yrt dluoc I" .yawa dekool ehS ".degagne
,enoyna no gnileef siht hsiw reven dluow I
ot hcterts swap s'neleH no swalc enilef eht sa dehctaw I
.rof deraperp t’nsaw ehs reffo na dna
.kcab reh no swap sih tup eh sa ylteiuq denaom ehS
.noitarbiv yreve ,tnerruc ria
.hself ym ta gnillup dna gnisaet ,smra ym gnola dekorts snolat reH
,snolat s'nohpyrg eht
.denetfos noisserpxe reh dna
.htaeneb swalc naiva ylacs
,em erofeb gnikcuf ylnotnaw seno eht erew yeht
"?kcits t'ndid tI—I"
,wolg tniaf a ees tsuj dluoc I ,daehA
,gab eht morf knird dna doof eht ekaT"
hcuot dna ssenrettib fo sraey net meeder ot ecnahc eht dah I
elzzum ym denepo I
.ssenoil eht dniheb deltsuh dna deddon tibbar ehT ".rae
.stsirw ym morf kcab gninnur sgniw railimaf ydaerla esoht ees ot gnitcepxe ,swap ym pu dleh I
ytnuoC moctahW .detcennocsid saw ti tub
,ylpeed ni dehtaerb neleH
.yrros m'I dna ti ees I
,swap ym pu dleh I
.tniop a dah ehs tub ,detatiseh I ".ebordraw
evitaitini eht koot I
,ytisoigiler ciretose
.tuhs gnippans part eht saw
,kcab ym buR" "?ssertsiM"
.rehto hcae tsap gnirats seye rieht
"?uoy hcuot ew yaM"
.dnim ym daer dah adisserC neleH
,meht ta derats I
edis tfel ym pu dellor erusaelp fo evawkcohs A
.tops eht no eid ot gniog saw I ekil tlef I
.flesreh gnikaerb ot esolc ylbidua saw ehs
detcepxe reven dah I
.delaeuqs dna daeh ym kcab werht I dna
,ksed ym no pu dewohs nac dna repparw ytpme eht ,yad txen ehT
.sredluohs dna smra ym gnicart
.retnec eht ta neleH htiw
.elcric dna elgnairt neewteb knird eht
.yalpsid no eno eht ekil tlef I tey dna
,sdrawkcab delttucs dna denrut I
,daehrevo no deppans thgil A ".dnatsrednu
.moc tod rettiwT fo yletal
.esaelp ,em wolloF"
.rac ym sdrawot detniop dna rood tnorf eht sdrawot dedilg eH
.ecifircas seriuqer tI
",lessev ytpme yM .si eh ytpme woH
.dnim ym ni revo dna revo sdrow eht dellor I "?os kniht I"
.s'ttibseN eht sdrawot dluoc I sa tsaf sa welf I sa elcric eht gnirrulb
,gnihtyna yfitsuj ot dah yeht rehtehw
.spil sih kcil ylwols dna elims mih ees ot emit ni tsuj neR ta pu dekool I ".uoy
,wap dereffo eht koot I
ngis a sa gnidaer taht koot uoY .htaeD dna
,deunitnoc neleH dna
.skraps fo rewohs a htiw ti otni deraeppasid neht
.krad eht ni yawllah gnol ylbissopmi na ekil tlef tahw nwod dna sriats fo thgilf a pu em dediug eh sa wap s'neR ot tsaf dleh I .ssenkcalb ykni
;enilffo si egapbew reH
.gniw rehto ym gnisserac ,ylteiuq dias neR
,rebmun reh dellac I
.yoj citatsce ni gnilkcarc seciov rieht
,srewop dna yrecros reh fo stroper knubed ot gnipoH
.sevlesmeht thgil ot nageb seldnac
.nwod sdap thgir ,pu sdap tfel
.uoy ot od tsuj nac I gnihtemos t'nsi sihT
:stniop wef a ot gniknirhs
.senil gniwolg eht fo owt neewteb ni s'ttibseN fo nac eht dna
,eye ym hctac ot txen eht rof hguone gnol tsuj ezag ym gnidloh ,efil ot derekcilf hcaE
.deveileb ev'dluow ylbaborp I ,ereht deppots d'ehs fi nevE .elbainednu
.sekat ti lla si traeh dna dnim nepo nA"
.elzzum reh revo daerps ti dna ,delahxe ehS
.sgniw ym fo elpoep ecnivnoc ot deirt d'I woH
.tfahs s'tibbar eht tsniaga denaom I dna
detniap a dna hsart reh tfel ehS
,tniop siht ta desuap neleH
,em sdrawot tuo mra sih dleh eH
"!eeht hceeseb ew ,xineohP"
.gniklat tuoba gnihtyna yas t'ndid neR tub
.sredluohs reh ssorca tuo gnidaf erofeb
.ssensuovren ym tsap em degdun sdrow s'neleH
.elzzum s'tibbar eht ssorca daerps elims esool A
.naom wol a esool tel ehs dna gab eht deppirg teef dewalc reH
hcuoc eht morf esor I
,ekaw s'erif eht nI
.sedahs eiree ni pu meht gnithgil
.moor eht dnuora lla
.elcric eht nihtiw su nioj dna ,tae
.sey dias I dna ,eciwt deksa uoY .sey dias I"
,tnemom taht ekat depleh I
,retnec eht morf yawa deppets I sa teiuq em tpek gnihtemos tub
,ti yned ot yrt lliw rotide yM"
,dekool neR dna neleH yaw eht ees dluoc I
srehtaef otni ruf reh gnignahc
.troffe suoiverp sih morf kcils llits
.si eh dexaler woh eeS .mih ta kool dna
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     ].yriuqnI
.lautir eht retne dna doof eht tae
.seye neerg-dlareme reh ni dlrow ym dleh adisserC neleH ".tnesnoc I"
,ni ehtaerb uoy sa em htiw tnuoc nehT"
.gnirts ollec a no gnidils wob a
.sevil rieht ni ecno tsael ta
,sraet ym hguorht reh ta pu dekool I ".yradnuob
.kconk ot tnemom eht rof wap ni gab htiw gnitiaw
,krow rieht tuoba tnew swap sih sA
.setunim owt tiaW
?sey yas I od woh ...woH
,retnec eht ni rabrettuN eht tup I
xineohP eht fo tirips eht leeF
,dloH .ruof ,eerht ,owt
,nac eht dna repparw eht tsniaga derekcilf thgil larutannu ehT
,gnihtaerB .ruof ,eerht ,owt
,elzzum sih teem ot kcab daeh reh detlit ehS
,ylwols pu doots neleH
.tfelc reh ta gnippal ,sgel detrap won reh neewteb daeh
.dnim ym no hcum oot dah I
.emalf fo selcric eht morf htrof tsrub sgniw tnecifingam owt sa
.ylthgils detsil llits kcen sih tub ,daeh sih tfil ot deirt eH
taht tuoba thgir neeb syawla
,on dias uoy nihtiw gnihtemoS
,raos ot snaem eht em tnarG
.bulc eht tiuq uoy erofeb tsuj gnidaer toraT a did uoY" .koohs ydob elohw reh dna kcab 'ssenoil eht otni desserp swalc s'neR .no gnuh I
,enitsuJ ,emit tsaL
2 traP ,ynnuB oK dna
,ydaer era uoy nehW"
sgniw wen ym fo ecnatsiser dna gut ehT
.lasuora htiw gnilkcarc dna thgila sevren
.gof kciht a dniheb tsol tlef sthguoht yM
;eb ot dedeen ti sa gnol sa
,meht neewteb yrtsimehc eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
;tfahs s'neR dnuora drawkwa saw drow ehT ".esolC"
reh ta pu kcab dekool eH
.taht tsap thgir deppils dah gnihtemos dna
trihs dna stnap ym dehs I
,nwo ym ni swap s'neleH koot I
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,sgaj gniyrc owt dah ev'I
.semalf eht morf gnurps
"?cigam eht rof ydaeR"
;cirtcele saw hcuot thgil taht nevE
",eb dluoc tahw htiw decalper si tahw fo sthguoht
;segnahc eht was uoY .did ew dna
.yradnuob taht detcepser lleps eht dna
.decnuob sserdda eht ot sliame rehtruF
.thgil eht sdrawot
;ti rof kcab og t'ndid I
.em edisni peed elgnit mraw a tlef I dna dehsulf skeehc ym ylneddus dna
,nwod dehcnelc swap reH
eb tsum uoy ,krow ot siht roF"
"?dnatsrednu uoy oD .eciohc ruoy
.ti devresed I kniht t'nod I dna ,ti detnaw I
,tsap nwo htiw detnorfnoc
.srae s'neR otni gnihtemos derepsihw dna
.ereht t'nerew uoy esuaceb
ytilibarenluv fo tnemom taht ni em ot delaever taht gnivah woh redisnoc dna
.deklat ehs sa sredluohs dna srae sih fo kcab eht gnittep
.niaga sdrow eerht esoht yas dluow I thguoht reven I
,eseht ees nac uoy ...uoY"
.krow drah s'tahT
,moor ywodahs eht hguorht deohce taht yrc a htiW
,semit eerht rabrettuN eht delcric thgil ehT
.denioj dah neleH taht won retsaf dellews htmraw dna gnilgnit ehT
,gniod neeb d'I tahw tsniaga romra ym saw
.skraps otni ffo gniliart
.ti ekat ot em gnitivni
.deliaf evah dluoc ti yhw snosaer ynam era erehT .ew did os
.delrufnu srehtaef nat
,nepo traeh rieht dna gnilliw eb ydob rieht fI
,spin neewteb reh ot derumrum eH
,citcamilcitna tsomla saw ti
.seye reh ni niaga enohs erofeb morf erif eht sa noitacinrof rieht deunitnoc neR dna neleH
.elcric eht fo retnec eht nihtiw ecalp reh koot neR sa gnitiaw
.mriuqs tibbar eht gnikam ,ralloc s'neR no deggut wap rehto reH
,tnemom yna ta ,saw tI .tsehc s'neR ot
.roolf eht no debircsni elcric regral neve na nihtiw yal taht
.srehtaef fo gnilffuhs teiuq a htiw nwo reh dexelf nohpyrg ehT ".ni
.eciov s'neleH htiw ekops dna
,sedis dna smra ym nwod gnilppir meht morf taeh eht
,ti seod eh elihw swap ruoy dloh nac I fi tseb krow ll'tI
,yhw uoy ot nialpxe t'ndluoc I ,on dnA
otni em gnignulp
.gnignol peed a yb dewollof
,em dniheb desolc rood ehT
senil klahc eht revo deppets I dna
;em edisni pu dellew htmraw ehT
.ralloc sih no yltneg deggut neht
.cisum eht hguorht tuc llits yeht tub
.detatiseh eh neht tub ,desiar swap siH
msagro fo yoj peed eht tlef I tub
,rehtaef eulb-dna-kcalb elgnis a
wenk I ysatnaf a
.traeh dna daeh ruoy rehtegot gnirb lautir eht tel dna knirD"
.devom ehs sa desaeler gnieb erusserp elbignat a ,kcab pets reh tlef I
,eveileb ot ecnahc a tub gnihton em reffo dluoc ,foorp on dah ehs taht noissimda dekan a saw tI
,desuora ydaerla saw eH
.sedalb redluohs eht htaeneb tsuj gnilcric dna gnittilps
noitalever taht dewollof taht maercs ehT
smelborp sti tuohtiw ton si gnihtaol-fles dezilanretni dna emahs detesolc ot aibohpreeuq yna ebircsa ot eslupmi ehT
.erom gnitsiser eb d'uoy thguoht I tub
,ananab laicifitra dna etalocohc paehc fo detsat rabrettuN ehT
,derrup ehs elihw rae reh dnuora dennirg tibbar eht woH
,sdniM gniriuqnI ,tnemom taht nI ".raos
.retsigaM ,seY" ".reh htiw wolloF
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.od uoy ecno niaga yrt dna
yreve leef dluoc—
stsif ym htiw roolf doowdrah eht dednuop I
,yad sa nialp ,saw ti erehT
,pohskrow eht fo tuo delbmuts dna sehtolc ym derehtag I
,yawa nrub ot demees ruf reh
,od ot gniog saw I tahw uoy nraw ot deirt I .era htob eW"
.ylwols daeh ym koohs dna hcuoc eht no detfihs I ".taht tpecca ll'I
"?taht fo trap eb ot tnesnoc uoy oD
,sdniM gniriuqnI ,draeh tsuj uoy dnuos tahT
,ytinummoc QTBGL eht NO
,aremac no meht dias t'ndah ehs hsiw I hcum revewoh ,sdrow s'neleH
.ti fo edisni gninihs elgnairt a htiw ,dnuorg eht no gniwolg elcric a saw ereht dna ,dehcaorppa I
.neR ot kcab denrut ehs dna ,ezorf I
;meht tuoba draeh ehs woh wonk t'nod I
.evaew ot tuoba er'ew segnahc eht ot nepo dna dexaler sa
QTBGL rof ytilibisnopser lla stup ti—
.eno sa gnikaeps owt eht
.noihsuc eht otno dna
,elcric eht fo egde eht ta