,siht ot del dah taht edosipe elohw eht gnirebmemer
.doog yltcefrep sŐti ,gniddik saw
ennaoJ sŐehs fi ton yllaicepsE
emit yreve ffo ti naelc mih edam tsuj ehS
,htiw em netaerht dluoc eh dnuora rekram cigam a saw ereht fi gnirednow ylbaborp dna ,trihs nwo sih ffo ekat ot tuobA Ő.tihs
ÓdeB eht rednUŇ   yojne esaelP
?ereht si ,tenalp ypirts a tŐnsi ereht
.ti ta gnihgual saw notloC
?ti dnif nac uoY
,tsrif ta sselmrah demees tI
yeHÔ Ő.sehciwdnas nocab uoy dna em gnikam sŐeh dias notloC kniht I
.tuo kool ,haeYÔ Ő.ho-
Ő Ó.raey siht uoy rof meht gniyub ton mŐI esuaceB
oDÔ .gninnirg detrats urD
,daeh ym no sdnah ym tup I
ti koot I nehw neethgie saw eh snaem taht dna
,nolas reh morf emoh edixorep
Ő.emit siht rekram eulb a desu eh sulP
,daD ta dekool urD woN
.haNÔ .gnikoms dekil eh dnuof notloC nehw
.emit tsrif eht meht degnarra dŐeh woh yltcaxe kcab meht gnittup peek dluow xileF os
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
loohcs dlo saw ehS
,selbbub ni derevoc sdnah siH
ydaerla pu nettog dŐeh dna
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
a ekil dnuos uoYÔ ,dias urD
Đ gnirb ot nettogrof dŐeh gnipoh flah saw I tahw tuo tog dna
,zeeJÔ .won nehctik eht fo tuo saw moM
neeb evah dluow kool gnivorppasid reh
?tsrif rethgil ym teg I nac
kcab daeh sih tup xileF
flesmih fo dloh a tog yllanif eh nehw dna
,dias I Ő,od I
,snooccar net fo dlohesuoh a ni samtsirhC sih gnidneps saw xof der-tessur
tops ot xileF ekil enoemos rof gniggeb tsuj
ehSÔ Ő?ruf ruoy saw ti nehw tuo rekram cigam
Ő.flesym ni detnioppasid os ma I dna
rednUŇŇ si yrots sŐyadoT dna
,deb latipsoh sih no yal eh elihw gnihtyreve dna
Ő,ekas sŐtsirhC rof
.did I gnidneterp
,ylsuoireS' .dias I ',ton
:suolaej gnittips-rehtaef
.mih htiw ekil saw ybab a htiw esuoh a ni gnivil tahw fo yromem yna dah reven eiflA os
,srac yot sih tog I
tŐndah I .dias urD Ő,wonk
sŐoccoRÔ .gnisuma etiuq saw yllautca tI .neht yakO
Ő,egnar sag eht gnithgil rof ereh ni eno speek
?trap tsrow eht dna
.thgir ti teg ot semit nezod a tsael ta ti elcric mih hctaw ot dah ylimaf eht hguoht neve
Ő?su fo rehtie egnahc ot htgnerts eht sŐohw tub
.eciiiiiNÔ Ő.ksed sŐtdnarbredliH srM morf gnilaets rof ssalc elohw sih fo tnorf ni esigolopa mih edam dna
,ti tuoba moM ot denihw eh nehW
,ssel neve tuo mih pleh ot tsuJ
Ő,xof ,ecalp siht ni no si erus gnitaeh ehTÔ .ereht yal dna
.devol enoyreve ohw yob nedlog a dna redlo sraey owt
.now syawla esuoh eht
!gabdnah sŐmom ym morf elots reve I gniht tsrif eht saw ti
Ő.ffo stnap dna trihs ym ekat annog mŐI kniht IÔ .dias I
doGÔ Ő.mih no taht gniraew loohcs ot gniog saw eiflA ruo
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil erŐuoY
saw noissecnoc ylno sŐmoM
,emit eht ta tuo moM gnipleh
.yob hsart ,yrt
yas dna dnuora gniyl ti tfel ew retfa
,rethgual eht ot sknaht elbanu
ereh gniyats saw amdnarg ym :og ew ereh ,woN
em no tniap-ruf yalp
.syadawon rettam gnihgual a saw siht yllufknaht sa tsuj dna
,hOÔ Ő.ffo diap saw elbat eht litnu ecnawolla sih esol dluoc eh ekil toN
llŐIÔ .draobpuc eht ni kcab ti gnittup dna etalp tsal
.skoob xis fo seires notloC dna ddoT eht rof nwonk tseb
,etunim a ni drah teg I llit liat ym krej nac uoy
,enim naht erom sih rehtar ro
,euc no thgir ni emac rehtorb cinahcem yM
enoyreve rof nus eht rednu sdrow esruc eht lla desu yltnecer dah ohw ,eiflA
,hOÔ .seye sih dellor notloC
sŐxof-lamina na fo noisserpmi suodnerroh
,emit taht ytrap loop ym ta regnuol nus eht no peelsa saw eh nehw ti tog adluohs I taht ekil zO fo cip a detnaw I
teLÔ Ő?yadot yako eb taht dluoW
a dekaens dah daD :ti tog I dna
.efil ym lla ni ,erofeb
,relddot a no ti esu ot desoppus ton erŐuoy desilaer ehs neht
liat nwo sih dehsurb
tahwÉrrrEÔ Ő?dnif ot em tnaw tŐnod uoy ereht rednu gnihton erehT
Ő,xileFÔ .rettahc-krab
?tol eht dennib ehs erofeb seye reh dellor dna
.mih tleb annog saw ehs
.rebmetpeS ni sŐyadhtrib sih zoc
.denrecnoc lla rof drawkwa ssel ti ekam ot tsuj
,edis sih koot yllautca ehs
,reppens dlo yffuts yrev a erŐuoy
.gnippohs su htiw gnimoc erŐuoYÔ .dias ennaoJ
ot gniog saw I .hguone saw
,mih ta gniralg-ekaf em was dna
.etihw ruf hcamots ym ekam ot dah ehs ;tŐndid
?yrots eht sŐtahWÔ .ti gnidloh
gnitirw peek ot tnaw mih edam tsuj taht esruoc fo
:oot yaw ym ti daer dah urD
tiaWÔ Ő.zO mŐI dneterp uoy elihw uoy kcuf em tel emoc dna
haeYÔ .gnivom morf mih gnippots ,enob eht yb thgir liat sih fo dloh koot dna
.ydaerla eert eht rednu sŐti dna ydaerla depparw si tneserp samtsirhC ruoy
.em ffo ti mirt ot reh rof hguone tuo werg ti litnu yad yreve
!retsam eht saw rehtorb gib ruoy gnola lla ,nmaddogÉuoy detah I dneterp ot deirt I nehw kcab loohcs ta uoy dellac reve I sgniht eht
drofleT srM lleWÔ .dias I
tŐnsIÔ Ő.ti etah setimret yltnerappa esuaceb radec desu eH
tuhs htuom xof ruoy kcol llŐti taht
tnew eh nehw dna
.dedolpxe lla tsuj dah anihc eht ekil dekool ycuL
taht nees reven dŐI
dias dna seye reh dellor moM
,tnecniV rMÔ .laer oot raf
Ő.yadretsey gnippohs rieht did ohw notloC dna ddoT morf trapA
sŐeHÔ .nehctik eht morf yawa gnipeek saw ohw
Ő.tnemom eht ta mih rof melborp tseggib eht yltcaxe si snisiar htiw gniyalp kniht tŐnod I
Ó?ecalp tsrif eht ni ybab rehtona deen ew did yhw
.moC tod rettiwT morf ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer
.niw ot dah tsuj eh nehw eiflA
thguoht ylsuoires I .ti rebmemer I
taht od dluoc eh wonk t'ndid I neve
.kcab ecnawolla ruoy evah nac uoy dediced evŐIŇ
.edis sŐurD nekat dah moM nehw
rehtona saw erehT Ó.eiflAŇ
,rac eht gnixif sŐeHÔ .dehgis ehS
,deb eht rednu morf tuo tsomla saw eH
deb eht otno debmilc I
ti etorw dna
,moMÔ .lio ni derevoc sdnah sih
Ótar nib a si ddoTŇ
Ő,ereht rednu tahTÔ Ő.eciiiiiNÔ
.epicer eeregdek sŐeibO ekam ot meht gnihcaet
Ő.DCO ruoy htiw gnissem si xirtaeB nehw uoy rof pu kcits tŐnow I emit txeN .niaga reve
em htiw nehctik dna elbat eritne eht pu hsaw dluoc notloC
adakeS ni raey tsal ruo saw tahT .siht teg
ehTÔ Ő?riahc a htiw tuhs eldnah rood a segdew enoemos fi seod ehs ekil tsuJÔ Ő.ni lla ,ni enO
,haeYÔ Ő.doog saw ehSÔ .dias I
,lios naitram eht sa ruoloc emas eht erŐyehT ?yhw wonk uoY
Ő!siht hctaw ,ddoT elcnU
moor ym ot pu gniog neht dna ,hcum os
tuo devom uoy nehw esoht dnuof ydaerla ylbaborp moM ruoy esilaer
!ahahahaaaaaAÔ .demia saw thgil eht erehw egnahc ot enohp sih htiw dnuora gnilbmuf ylsuoivbo
Ő?taht sŐtahw ,etunim a
,gnihgual sedis sih dehctulc eH
,DCO fo citamotpmys saw yllautca siht desilaer dŐehs erom eht
,erofeb seman tsrif rieht draeh tŐndah yllautca notloC
,yawyna boj a teg dna
ffo looc og ot reh dlot daD esuaceb tŐndid ylno ehS
'.ooz eht ta emit gnideeF
,xof eht htiw ykcuf
.ti saw taht dna Ó!mih etah I
peelsa saw I nehw pu trihs ym dellup eH
yllautcAÔ Ő?erehwyna sodeeps ni zO fo eno tog uoY
detaoc-retniw-lluf
.eohs reh htiw ssa eht no eiflA dekcahw ehs
ŐÉtiaWÔ .tey enod tŐnsaw I desilaer notloC
,kniht dluow daD ym tahw erac tŐndid ehs dna
rotterubrac taht egnahc ot tog evŐuoy
lliWÔ .dekaerc emarf eht os dluoc I sa hcum sa deb eht no tuoba gnimriuqs ,ti did I
eciNÔ .sriats eht pu kcab mih dewollof I
llAÔ :rof gnitiaw neeb dŐI tahw dias eh
,dedlof smra sih htiw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
yeHÔ  :tenretni eht no siht nees dŐeh em dlot dŐeh ecnis rof gnitiaw neeb dŐI ekil tsuj
,moooMŇ ot tog eh tsal ta nehT
?taht gniod tiuq uoy
Ő?tog uoy lla tahtÔ
,daD ot dias I Ő,doG hOÔ
:sageV saw mom ruo tub
,emarf sŐdeb ym fo tals a otno nettirw tsuj tŐnsaw tI
,haeYÔ Ő.yad taht ees ot evila tŐnerew yeht fi nevE
,areV dellac drapoel wons hsitirB esnesnon-on
?etunim a ni deb ruoy rednu og I fi yako uoy era
no deerga dah yerfmoC rD
,fo scip tcelloc ot desu I sremmiws saw ti ,dnoceS
llaWÔ .gnimoc saw tahw gniwonk
desu ehs ,ÓmŐIŇ toN
.daeh sih morf trapa
,nrob saw I dna
rebmemer ot deen lla ew dna esuoh siht ni tseug a si notloC
,gab sŐmoM ni dnah a gnittup fo gnikniht erŐyeht ekil
- em ot laiceps yllaer sŐrethgil taht dnA
eht reh evag urD Ő.reve
,derugif dŐI sa tsuJ Ő.suoiraliH
Ő!ti hctaw sŐtel
,moM ot ti evig attog evŐI
Őtar nib a si eiflAÔ etorw dna
ti fo llems eht morf pu werht eH
.sekoj xof eht fo hguone dah evŐew kniht I
sexoFÔ .llac enohp a gnirud notloC llac eibO
taht teg ehs did woh dnA
sraey eseht lla dna
?thgir stnerap sŐdaD ruoy sŐtaht
?tsafkaerb rof
.ylimaf a sa llam eht ot gniog lla erŐeW
.dooGÔ Ő?raf taht ecnuob ti did woH !ti togÉew dna
,kroY weN morf rehcaet onaip sih etatimi
,haoWÔ .ti od ot emit nedlog a saw siht tub
eciNÔ  Ő.ereht thgir cip flow lageL .daeha oG
',yrroSÔ '.lla ti draeh ev'I dna
.tnemugra elttil yrev htiw nehctik eht ni tsafkaerb gnikam enil-
.noertaP sih no ,eerf rof elbaliava
hguonE .niaga gniog
.pu tsal eht saw I gniwonk
IÔ Ő.taht dias I ecnis siht gninnalp neeb sŐeH
shtnom wef a ni neetxis eb dŐehS .gurhs
,yrtneprac sekil rehtafdnarg yM
,ti yas ot gniyrt tpek notloC
yawa syot sih fo hcnub a koot ehs dna
,did daD sih tahw gniod reven sŐeh dna
Ő,nam gnuoy ,yadot VT erom
.ereht rednu tnew rethgil ym kniht
.lausu naht gninrom eht ni ti rof rekciht
Ő?dekup uoy dna ti htiw etteragic tsrif ruoy ekoms uoy edam ehSÔ Ő.retal raey A
?I tŐndid ,raeY weN eht ni nep epav eht tsuj ot og dŐI uoy desimorp I ?taaaahWÔ Ő.xof ,ekaspeek emoselohw a hcus ot
:retteb eno tnew moM ,hguoht woN
,tsriFÔ Ő?tneserp samtsirhC ym ro
,nocab dna segasuas
,taht did ohw eiflA saw ti gnihtyna uoy teb llŐI
.ti daer I nehw dias I
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
taht gnikooc rof tsuj taht dediced I
,sediseB' .dias notloC
.yrc elttab a ekil erom dednuos taht krab gnirettahc a evag dna
ruOÔ .dias adleZ Ő,gniyats
.evah uoy kniht yam uoY .notgnirdlA
.dlrow eritne eht ta saw eh dam woh rof
?esuoh siht ni ehtaerb I nac ,moM
oD' '!niaga taht oD !haoW'
eiflAÔ Ő?amabalA morf sremraf nottoc ehT
hUÔ Ő.raeB elffulF rM tog I
,tser a ydob ruoy evig ot ediced uoy sthgin tsom no gniknird fo skeew retfa nehw teg uoy tahw
.ees ot em tnaw tŐnod uoy deb ruoy rednu gnihtemos si ereht
Ő?doof htiw yalp ot mih gnigaruocne ton tuoba uoy dlot I evah tahw
eno siht piks esaelp
.mih rof moor eht ssorca meht dekcilf urD sa htuom sih ni snisiar hctac ot dedeecorp dna ,dias ydderF
,kroY weN ni egelloc fo sraey flah a dna owt retfa samtsirhC rof xineohP ni emoh gnieB
noitcudorp ot ylimaf eritne ym tog
,edih dluoc ohw gniees fo tuo ekoj a edam ylimaf ruo flah
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.hgual tub pleh tŐndluoc I Ő.allisurD ,ton
.rood egdirf eht no
,em htiw xes gnivah erŐuoy elihw tar nib
tog dna Ő?tar nib
.noops reh deppord urD
.sraM morf era
meht dlot I ,hgrreeelB
.dik a saw I nehw em rof siht edam eh
Đ Őrevognah esreverÔ
,eno eud erew eW
.yadretsey ti dehctaw dŐeH
mŐIÔ .ti tuoba thguoht neve tŐndah ylbaborp dna
.sehtolc wen emos rof pu evas si
,no llits thgil eht
?adnap der a saw eibO yas uoy tŐndiD !fraB
,ti tae ot tnaw tŐndid yeht fi neve sdnoces dah enoyreve oS
.thguoht I ,nmaddog doog a rettam tŐndid tI
esion taht ekam ton od dnA .nihplod
dah dah reve I nrop eht flah dnA
Ő,ennaoJ ,looc sŐtIÔ Ő.srennam ruo
,ttub sih dekcams yllufyalp I
:yltcerroc desseug ydaerla dŐeh tahw gnigami ylbaborp
gniht elohw eht dias dna
a dellac I tahw dah I gninrom sihT
.rac eht rof ydaer dna desserd tog esle enoyreve elihw
hsiFÔ .ydderF htiw moor gnivil eht ni reh deciton
.enituor sŐoccoR od dna ni klaw neht
,mooooM ?moor ym fo tuo
,saw ereht yllufknahT
,uoy gnillet peek I
.deb ym otni siht gnihctarcs dna
,gnitae tŐnerew uoy fi neve laem yreve rof elbat eht ta tis ot dah uoy woh tuoba elur bmud reh dexaler yllanif dah moM ecnis revE
.rehtom ruoy htiw tnemugra na niw reven uoY
.efink nep a htiw ylbaborp
yaWÔ Ő.thgil ffo tog I kniht I
.eiflA hsinup dŐeh dna
.tihs dna doof tnalp yhtlaeh dna nairategev lla erew yeht thguoht I
,nozamA no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.esuoh eritne eht rof ecnawolla on sŐti
,retlif leuf wen a teg dna
,allisurDÔ .gninrom siht gnilims saw retsis ym tsael tA
notgnirdlA ddoT yb
ti ni nihploD dna kcirT
.ti gniod elbat gninid a deniur eH
ksed sŐrehcaet sih morf rekram cigam a elots eH
.kool dna ereht nwod teg
Ő,xof erutammi yrev a era uoy
Ótar nib a si ddoTŇ
lufituaeb ym ,notloC
,won kcab daeh sih tup eH
?rehtorb elttil sih no gniward mih rof od ehs did lleh eht tahw
Ő.niaga trats tŐndluow ti
.tsrif ti was ehs dna
Ő?dnAÔ Ő.deb ym rednu erŐuoy elihw noitasrevnoc a gnivah erŐew
,hOÔ Ő?ereh thgir nettirw sŐtahw nees uoy evah ,ddoT
mih neht ,revo dellor eH
,ekoms tŐnod I zoc ,annog tŐnia uoy
.ereh ylimaf eht tuohtiw kcuf
gnisu peek ot dah ehs os
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,syadiloH yppaH
,yot knik etiruovaf ruo
,tuo flesmih dellup notloC
ecnawolla erom on sŐti
sekoj xof lausu eht htiw pu tup dna
tuo srepmuj dna strihs-t fo tes eritne sih tog ehS
siht thguorb ehS
,nooccar haey
.pot rof nrut ym sŐtIÔ .og mih tel I
.doog eb attog sah siht
hOÔ .niaga dehgual notloC
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
retfa gnol ton ylbaborp reh no erifkcab ylitliug tnemhsinup reh evah ot ylno
oNÔ Ő.taht retfa deppots
uoYÔ .dias moM Ő,ton era
.ecno esrup reh morf hsac elots eiflA .emas yrev
.yad tsafkaerb paehc a no erew ew fi egdirrop tsael ta ro
,dekcap dŐeh gab eht ni kcab rethgil sih tup eH
erehWÔ .dah tsuj I tahw gnisilaer
.gnihtyreve fo tuo rekram cigam teg ot syaw eht lla wenk ehs
Ő,seYÔ Ő.seod xof eht zoc saw llems taht dna
Égninrom siht ylnO
,samtsirhC rof mih nevig dah
Ő.rethgil taht ekil yllaer I
,mih ot lautir yliad a emoceb dah siht ekil gnittes elbat
.notloCÔ Ő.dnatsrednu dŐuoy taht od ot sllab eht dah reve dŐuoy fI
morf meht gnitteg neeb dŐeh erehw desilaer ehs nehw
.enog erew sdrow eht litnu egarag eht morf tirps etihw fo nac a htiw sruoh
.egats ybab eht tsap detsal ti dnA
Ő.rac sŐoccoR ni edir nac
,relevart wollef ruoy
.pu frab em sekam rac
,yeHÔ .delley ydderF Ő!E-
IÔ Ő?rof taht od annaw uoy od
,uoy gnitpmexe eton kcis a ylno htiw
.pu thguorb saw daD woh wonk uoY
.ecnahc eht ssim tŐndluoc I .deb ym rednu lwarc ot detrats dna sruof lla no tog eH
gninrom eno loohcs otni eiflA dehcram neve ehS
eiflA dlo raey xis a
Đ kroY weN morf tŐnsaw yllautca ohw
Ő.urD ,reh ta raews ot evah tŐndid uoYÔ
,ereht ti dehctarcs dah eiflA
,latipsoh eht ni sŐdaD siHÔ .dias daD
sŐtahTÔ .deb eht ta detniop I
htiw pu emoc ot elba neeb ylno ecno dah
enoNÔ .su fo tser eht sa flesreh ta hcum sa ,dias moM
.gnihgual deppots eh sa ffo koohs eH
,kool Őydal gnuoyÔ ro
,ekawa saw moM erofeb dneirfyob ym htiw gninrom taht etteragic tsafkaerb
fIÔ .nwod kcab trihs sih dellup eh
,notgnirdlA ddoT yb ÓdeB eht rednUŇ saw sihT     Ő.keew a rof
,etihw mŐI erehw hcamots ym nO .em no
,pih ym no dnah a
nemerif nooccar dekan fo noitcelloc ruoy ti sI
.mom ruoy morf elots reven uoy yhw wonk I won ,nmad-
IÔ .no krims Őtihs taEÔ reh tup urD
enog ecnawolla ,mooB
,dias I Ő,thgil
Ő,nam gnuoy ,tnemom ruoy yojnEÔ teg yam uoY
.laer saw ti ,gninrom sihT
,samtsirhC siht tegdub gnippohs sŐylimaf ym ot yenom dedda dah notloC
Ő,lleHÔ Ő.ti ta dekool I emit yreve
.ssim tŐnac uoy srettel fo dnik eht ni ,meht fo lla no
htiw od syug uoy od tahWÔ
eulav latnemitnes laer hcatta uoy wonk ot
,elims ot tnaw did I hguoht neve ecaf ym no kool napdaed a ,pu kcab tog I
rethgual dik suoyoj ym gniyojne dna
neve si daeh ruoy dna ,kcor a ekil peels uoy
.sŐregrepsA sih htiw og ot
ÓnoinueR samtsirhC AŇ
uoYÔ Ő?uoy tŐndid ,seugolatac raewmiws eht dnuof uoYÔ
,tsafkaerb hguorht lla
,mih ffo enohp sih koot I
.did ehSÔ Ő!tŐndid ehS
.ydal gnuoy ,gninrom siht wodniw eht denepo I nehw gniod erew uoy tahw dellems
,niaga dennirg nehT
,neht no oG .xof
dnAÔ .hgiH adakeS ta maet gnimmiws eht no tŐnsaw zO
tekcop ym fo tuo emoc atsuM
,ereh neeb dŐehs fi dna
teg annaWÔ dias dna
.taht retfa gab reh morf elots ydoboN .yracs os tog lla ti yhw sŐtaht
,uoy hctac I yad ehT
od ot tnaw annog erŐuoy gniht tsrif eht kniht I tuB
,eno taht fo thguoht reven yllaer I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
nwog gnisserd ym ni sriatsnwod tnew I
.ti peek dluoc I em dlot neht dna
uoYÔ .niaga llabyeknoM repuS no slevel trepxE eht mrots notloC hctaw ot detnaw ehs ,sdrow rehto nI
dnAÔ Ő.gniog peek mih edam llits ehs dna
thgit os uoy no elzzum siht parts annog mŐI
,sŐOFU ekil thgin yb levart yeht
,elbat eht rof tog eh tahw saw taht
Ő?ttub ruoy gniffuts enod mŐI retfa pu thgil nac I os tsuJ
,elletnahC ekil tsuj eb dluow tahT
etorw dna emoh ti thguorb dna
,loohcs eht ta eiflA
Ő?tfel gnihtyna erehT
.ogniBÔ Ő.gnihtyreve no
Ő.em tisybab nac notloC
.ydaerla snug gib eht dah moM
ti gnitah ereht doots eiflA elihw
,yeHÔ .mih morf draeh reve dŐI noitseuq tseddo eht ebyam em deksa eh
,mih thguac ohw eno eht neeb dah urD
Ő.em gnillet erŐuoy
?ereh nwod gnikooc saw tsafkaerb fo dnik lleh eht tahW
.radec fo edam sŐtI
,haeYÔ .retal sraey neetfif doog a
elbat eht no tuoba yreltuc dna sehsid eht gnivom rof gninrom siht reh ta og a dah dah urD retfa gniklus llits saw xirtaeB
,teiuq tnew moor eht woN
IÔ Ő!pu sserttam a dloh llits nac gniht siht dezama erew uoy dias ohw eno eht erŐuoY
Ő.namow taht htiw ecnawolla eht syawlAÔ Ő.eyb-eyb
mih teg uoy lliw ,moooM
.em ot meht evag dna
oSÔ Ő.ekoms og annaw uoy fi eno taht worroBÔ .dias I
.gnieb saw eh yob diputs a tahw desilaer eh litnu
,xileFÔ :ti no saw moM dna ,won moor eht ot kcaB
tsom eht evag dna
dias tsuj dna notloC ta derats xileF ,tnelis tnew moor eht nehW
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
Ő,ennaoJ ,nuf rieht evah meht
eht gniyrd ,dias eh
,keew a sgnivas skcub eerht no sehtolc nwo sih ecalper ot droffa dluoc eh litnu dnA
,dnalgnE tsew-htuos morf rohtua yrruf dehsilbup-fles a
Ő.teerts eht fo htgnel eht uoy hcnual lliw moM
'.siht saw yas ot tnaem xileF tahw kniht I
Ő?tsafkaerb rof ni emoc ot mih dlot uoy fo
.ereht oS .reveroF
a em llac uoy fi
,rediw neve nirg mih edam tsuj taht dna
Ó.tar nib a si ddoTŇ .hgual
.detfarc ylgnivol os ecno dah rehtafdnarg ym tahw gniniur
Ő?tar nib a ddoT sŐyhW
.sretto dekil I dnA .nemerif ton
.hoÉfo tuo tihs eht lla gniggolcnu peek tŐnac I
Ő,looCÔ Ő.emos neht dna lla ti tog evŐuoy esuaceb ydaerla ti nees evŐuoy dna
eeregdek kcoddah dekoms ylkcis ,yllems
,lleWÔ .sseldrager ti gnisol ogre
,yad eno loohcs morf emoh steg eh nehw sŐtahT
.ffuts taht raeb tŐnac I htob
,moC tod rettiwT morf
hOÔ .ees ot hguone rednu
,yakoÉmorf era snooccar dnA .ot dah
Ó?tog uoy lla tahTŇ
?hsart ni derevoc tenalp eritne na snaelc taht tobor eht htiw mlif if-ics taht saw tahw ,xileF
,lareneg ni ruoivaheb sih dehctaw dah moM erom eht tub
rof egdirf eht burcs mih edam llits ehs tub
,gninrom siht litnU
.rewop eht dah ehs won dna
mom ym edam ylterces wenk I tahw enod dna
.rekram cigam eht htiw og tsal eno rof tnew eh nehT
Ő?ot tnaw I oD .doG
skool sa hcum os enoyna fI
Ő.rotinom llŐew dna enilredrobÔ
,gniklat thgiarts a saw ehs
,thgiled sŐmoM ot hcuM
moMÔ  Ő.thgin tsal riahc ruoy no snaej ym gnittup saw I sa
.gniht elohw eht deifisnetni tsuj eciov ym yb nekops ti gniraeh notloC
yrots a em gnidaer otni tseretni reh lla tup moM sa skool etah ylrehtorb suolaej em gnivig
,notloCÔ Ő?shtom taht
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.taht tsuj naht syaw erom ni kaerb a dedeen ydob ym ekil tlef I
,trats laem eht tel
:sgniht owt wenk I tub
,selffaw ot eson ym gniwollof neeb evah dluohs I
.tey ynnuf tŐnsaw ti htiw gnissem yhw teg etiuq tŐndid xirtaeB
.esrow htiw pu emoc tŐnac ehs skniht llits eh ,naM ?eiflA dnA
?pu tuhs mih ekam uoy lliw ,moooMŇ
nac yeht os emoh yats ot gniog era notloC dna ddoT
draeh dŐeh tahw gniypoc ,dias eh Ő,C
Ő.esenaitraM ni tneulf erŐyeht dna
.og ew ereh ,doG hO'
.neht hcraes og
Ő.saw ti esruoc fOÔ .dias moM
ereht fo tuo teg woN
nwo sih tog sŐeh won sdik kcams ohw elpoep rof nottub kresreb a tog sŐeH
.looc ton sŐmoM ruoy morf gnilaets ,yako ,haey
.oppiz reh dah I dnuof ehs nehw oot em dehsinup mom ym yhw sŐtahT
efiw xe eb-ot-noos sih tellub eht morf gnirevocer
,ssem eht ,srepaid eht ,esion ehT .tihs ho dna
.dnif ot skeew reh koot taht secalp ni ti gniod detrats eH
oNÔ  .erofeb yad eht dnA
,stnaprednu ym ni em dnif ot
,eriotreper eht ot dedda xileF neht
Ő.taht em eviGÔ Ő.was reven uoy
,llew ytterp ti derevoc dah ehs tpecxE .moM ,eno eciN
neeb dŐI yttihs woh em dnimer ot tsuJ
.ees ot reisae saw ti os
tsuJÔ .won yllis erom neve rethgual sih
,detah I epicer
.srae reh derevoc adleZ
,dias notloC Ő,neht no oGÔ Ő?taht
Ő!huuuuUÔ Ő!morf era snooccar erehw sŐtahT
.eromyna hcum os mih no gnieb ton noitnetta sŐmoM
!hOÔ .tnemom a rof ni siht ekat notloC tel I
.eta occoR elihw elbat eht ta gnittis peek ot dah lla ew
syas dna elims elttil siht no stup ehs dna
,yrots yadiloh rehtona dna
,noitatlusnoc gnol a retfA
.ydobyreve ,sknahT .taerg ,lleW
Ő,duol tuo gniyrc rof hOÔ Ő?occoR si
?taht rof teg eh did tahW
em ni saw ehs detnioppasid woh em dlot tsuj ehS
Ő.sŐyraM dna knaH ta remmus elohw a htiw denetaerht tog eH ?elbat ehT
dnAÔ .mih morf yot ruo gnikat
em htiw emag emos gniyalp ro
,notgnirdlA ddoT yb ÓÓdeB eht
,eiflA naht regnuoy raey a ylno
tsuJ' .dias notloC
esuoh siht ni ekoms uoy fi dnA
daeh ym dekop dna
,ffuts gnirebmemer detrats eh nehT
.esrow saw ffuts otni ti gnihctarcs derugif eH
gnitaeper peek dluow