.fles laer ruo si nosrep taht
.lla ti gniyas elims ym ,dennirg I
”.ecitcarp fo stol dna stol snaem tsuJ“  .dekniw ydoK
.detresed demees osla tub seert dna ssarg emos fo weiv ecin a dah tI
,deddon neht dna denworf nniMcM
.dednopser dah rethciR was dna ppa eht denepo I
.em ta dekool dna trihs sih no gnillup saw flow citelhta ehT
.t’nsaw yllaer I tub ,taht ekil detacilpmoc saw I thguoht eh taht etaicerppa I  .no
.drawrof semoc revetahw ecaf dna ffo ksam taht ekaT
”?uoy gnirehtob s’tahw neeb siht saH  .yug roop uoY“
.dnuora emac yeht nehw meht htiw trilf ,setad dna slrig tuoba sesucxe pu ekaM
.elbat eht no em fo tnorf ni gab ym
”,ereh neeb reven ev’I“   ”.mrod
.guh thgit a ni em dleh tsuj eh tub ,mih naht reggib saw I
.taht retfa ylbbow elttil a teg syawla sgel yM“
.yag sa tuo emoc dah eh ecnis syug wef a yb detagorretni neeb ylbaborp dah eH  .suoixna gnikool rof ydoK emalb t’ndluoc I
,flesmih dnif ot gniyrt ,sallaD ,emit tsaL
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,gninnirg saw ydoK
”.sgniht yas annog era elpoeP
.yltfos dias eh ”,laaaaD“
.sallerbmu dna selbat htiw ecarret llams a ot gnidliub eht dnuora gnipparw
,esolc gnihsup dna mih dnuora mra na gnilruc ,deddon I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.esaeler a retfa nwod gniog saw noitcere ym taht ro ,ykcits saw I taht erac t’ndid I  .mih ot esolc gnihsup dna flesym gnitnap ,dias I ”,woW“
.sgnileef ym tuo tel I sa tup deyats I erus gnikam
.sdrow mraw ,dnik esoht draeh I nehw flesym detcelloc yllanif dah I
.ffuts siht tuoba gnihtyna wonk t’nod I
,niaga aera eht ni reve er’uoy fI
): .setelhta egelloc owt htiw od dluoc I sgniht ehT
.dennirg dna nwod tas ydoK
”.laD ,tpecnoc emaS“
.yrarbil a ot supmac hguorht em tel ydoK
.nwo sih enola tel
”?maet olop retaw eht denioj I kniht uoy od yhW“
gnilgnatnu fo krow eht nigeb ot ecalp on htiw
”.etammoor sih htiw pu em kooh ot deirt neve snevetS
peed a gnikaT   ”.esimorp I
.yug a ot gniklat m’I nehw elbatrofmoc erom hcum os leef I…tuB
”.larutan a er’uoY“
,wonk uoy ,pots ot detnaw uoy oS“
.egnarts adnik s’ti…tI“ .deddon I    ”?thgir
”?dnim ruoy no s’tahw oS“
.yaw taht deyats ew gnol woh rebmemer t’nod I
.mih fo tnorf ni nwod ti gnilttes erofeb eeffoc sih fo lluf elzzum rehtona koot dna delims ydoK
,eromyna ni delttob ti peek ot evah t’ndid I
lla…lrig eht naht erom yug eht gnihctaw dna setammaet ym delbmeser taht seiceps fo nrop pu gnikool ,sthguoht esoht ,skool dekaens esoht llA  .kcab gnikool ,eurt saw ti tuB
,nemiger gniniart siht htiw yako m’I“
.mrod eht fo tuo teg ot deen I fi yduts ot emoc I erehw si sihT“
,ti ot pu gnileef er’uoy fI“
.ecneirepxe yag tsrif s’enoemos no kram a eb ot tnaw t’ndid I
,trops eht tuoba deklat ylerab ew was dna segassem dlo ruo hguorht tnew I
.ffo tlef gnihtyreve tuB
,denoitnem I flow taht ot deklat I dna sdneirf ym dlot ev’I tuB
,thgir erew uoY
.ti rof flesym deleets dna ot klat ot dah I ohw wenk I
.thgir leef t’ndid tsuj ti dna ,lrig a htiw ecno xes gnivah deirt I
.detniat saw pihsdneirf yna tnaem ti esuaceb aedi taht ekil t’ndid I
.kniht em edam osla yeht tub em truh sdrow ruoY
”.thgir sleef tsuj gnihtyrevE
.ksam a gniraew saw I  .wonk uoy
.gnihtyna ro em dekcolb dah eh noitacidni yna yllaer t’nsaw ereht tub evitca saw eliforp siH
”.looc er’eW“  .dennirg I
?tuo emoc uoy did yhW
.llew tuo dekrow ti ekil sdnuos ti tub uoy rof nossel a eb ot thgin taht rof tnaem reven I   ,laD
,ecalp tcefrep siht wonk I  !taerG“
.wonk I bup siht ta rennid evah s’tel
.erofeb tlef reven d’I sgniht leef em edam s’eh dna ppa na no yug siht ot gniklat neeb ev’I tuB
.peels ym ni od ot elba neeb evah dluohs I taht syalp gnissim saw I taht hcum os derednaw dnim ym ecitcarp ni dna ,sessalc ni sucof ylerab dluoc I
.yag sa tuo emac ohw maet ruo no eno eht
tub…em rof snoitseuq evah dluow eno on ,tuoba yrrow ot eno oN
”.yllaD ,peelsa llaf t’noD  .xaler tsuJ  !dooG“
elbaliava ,seirots gniK nomiS fo ygolirt rieht dehsilbup yltnecer ohw
.yug rehtona htiw ti enod reven ev’I
.ton m’I enoemos eb ot dneterp ot evah dluow I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.xniL-edirP no egassem A
.elboN dna senraB hguorht
.mih ta yrgna llits saw I
.seye sih ni ssenlufepoh fo tnilg llams a
.gniyrd ylwols ylleb s’ydoK no diuqil mraw eht tlef dna tib a eenk ym detfihs I
.ffuts yag siht fo tol a hguorht em gnidael neeb s’eH
”.euqinhcet ruoy no krow ot evah ot gniog er’ew ,ynnuf klaw em ekam ot tnaw uoy fI“
,iaK yb daeR yb uoy rof daer
.tnemom a rof thguoht I
.no em nrut ot deganam syawla ti dna sessik sih dniheb htgnerts eht leef dluoc I  .thgir os ,os tub
”?gniog yako llits uoY
.sdneirf llits er’ew mih no tih t’ndid I fi em dlot eh tub
.daeh ym deddon I tub ecnetnes eht hsinif t’ndluoc I
”edirP gniksamnU“   yojne esaelP
.ffuts dna seitrap ta ti fo tuo kcab ot syaw dnuof syawla I ,haeY“
.ffo ksam ym koot I taht wonk ot uoy detnaw tsuj I
,sallaD  .ton er’yeht
.thgin taht ecnis teiuq gnieb rof uoy emalb t’nod I   ,rethciR yeH
.dnatsrednu yam ohw
.spitregnif sih neewteb rettulf ti gnittel ,srae dednuor ym fo eno htiw deyalp dna pu dehcaer eH  .gnitrofmoc
”?flesruoy noitseuq uoy edam taht ecneirepxe yna evah uoy diD  .gnuoy er’yeht nehw wonk ot dnet
.rethciR morf egassem on llits saw erehT  .xniL-edirP ot revo gnippilf dna neercs eht ta nwod gnikool
gnittup ,mih morf ssorca nwod tas dna dias I
taht lla rof tuB  .emit gib
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ytpmE  .teiuQ
.yad eno ecitcarp retfa deksa I ”?nniMcM“
.flow ruoy gnirb ot erus ekam tsuJ
.srehtaef s'enoyna delffur ton dna ,detsixe ,wonk uoy…tsuj ev’dluoc uoY
”.sallaD sa ti decaf evah ll’uoy ,dab ro doog ,dne eht nI
.spil eht no ,yltneg ,em dessik dna em ta dehgual ydoK   ”.niaga
.flesym evol ot dediced dna flesym detpecca I oS
,soroboruo na si tI
.detsuahxe dna deveiler tlef ylneddus I taht dezilaer I nehw dna
,ddo tlef yug a gnissiK
,ereht dna ereh ruf sih fo sdne eht ot gnulc taews fo sdaeb tniaF
.ssa ym ot pals lufyalp a dna liat ym ot gut a htiw dedrawer saw I
.etuc yllufwa er’uoy ecnis ,oot ,emahs a s’tI
”?taht ekil gnihtemos od ot ediced uoy edam tahW
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.yalpsid lluf no erew selcsum tfiws dna tcapmoc siH
,rethciR suoiretsym eht teem ot tnew
”.em no skrow syawla ti tuB“
,em eb tsuj ot em dlot dah eno oN
.spil sih ot pu neht ,ereht mih dessik dna kcen sih otni eson ym deirub I
.skeew wef tsal eseht em ot tnatropmi os emoceb dah ohw flow eht ta kcab gnikool erofeb ylfeirb ti ta nwod dekool I
”.elpoep rehto rof ksam a gniraew
,tcefrep s’retaW“
swonk eh nosrep eno eht ot tuo sehcaer
.su brutsid ot emac eno oN  .em draeh eno oN
.sredluohs ym ffo detfil thgiew eguh siht tlef I taht rebmemer tsuj I
”.lla si dnim ym no tol a tog tsuJ“
.drarreG ot klat yltcaxe t’ndluoc I dna enoemos ot klat ot dah I wenk I
ton…naem I  !seY  .oN  .seY“   ”.ti…tuoba
.dedispol emoc dah taht tah ym xif ot gniyrt dna eson ym gnipiw ,deddon I
”?erus rof ekiL
?ees uoy oS“  .dehgual ydoK
,noos emit yna edarap a nwod rehtael raew ll’I tbuod I hguohtla dnA
.won tuo gniog er’ew tuo snruT
.kcen ym no ruf eht hguorht sregnif sih dehsurb dna kcab ym debbur flow eht ”?yako gniod uoY“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”.redluohs eht ni em dehcnup eh dna nis sa ylgu saw eh mih dlot I
,srewsna eht lla evah I yas t’nac I
.tuoba gniklat saw I tahw fo esnes ekam ot gniyrt
,debbos I sa redluohs sih ni deirub saw ecaf yM
”?reve emit tsrif ruoy ti saW
.ydoK ,deracs os m’I“
.ti skaerb gnihtemos litnu
.ti fo ekam ot tahw wonk t’nod I
?esle enoyna llet ssel hcum
.rennid evah s'tel ,haey ,yawynA
.thginot yllar EDIRP taht ot gniog er’eW
,suovren elttil a m’I  ?yltsenoH“
.mih no nwad ot demees ti
,sriats enots emos pu dna edistuo tnew neht dna mraw gnihtemos tog htob ew erehw efac llams a saw roolf tsrif eht nO
.snosaer thgir eht rof lla saw ti tub ,derudne dah I niarts eht
.nirg yppah tub derit a htiw em ta dekool dna daeh sih gninrut ,gnitnap saw eH
”?rewohs eht rof ydaeR
.yug emosewa na era uoy dna ,smaerd dna sehsiw ruoy ,efil ruoy s’tI
etelpmoc leef mih gnikam neeb dah ohw nam eht taht revocsid ot ylno
gniog saw thguoht eh tihsllub revetahw ro ”,ksam a gniraew“ saw I nehw em ot klat ot tnaw t’ndid eh sseug I  .ylenoL
.gnihton…won tub ,ecitcarp retfa gnitiaw meht dah ro ,emit eht lla meht tog yllausu I
.rethciR morf segassem eht saw taht dna ,syad ym ni gnissim saw I tahw wenk I
enoemos llet ot egaruoc eht fo rettam a ylpmis s’ti
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.deddon ydoK ”,thgiR“
---   ”?kcaJ deleeH gnirpS nomed eht tuoba raeh reve
.rethciR morf egassem on llits saw erehT
.gnidnatsrednu dna pleh rof gnignol peed a htiw ydoK ta derats I  .skeehc ym nwod llor sraet tlef I   ”?…uoy era…laD“
emussa llew yrev yam ew neht ,srehto fo tifeneb eht rof demrofrep anosrep eslaf a sa sevil ruo lla devil evah ew fI
.moorhtab eht edisni morf emac eciov s’ydoK ”?did uoY“
?esle enoyreve ot uoy era tahw ,era uoy ohw ot eurt t’nera uoy fi
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.emosdnah dna ,dekan saw eH
.ti ebircsed ot yaw revelc yllaer a yllautca s’tahT“
”!nom’C  .laD ,desucof uoy deen ew dna noos emag a evah eW
ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb ”edirP gniksamnU“
.gnorw gnihtemos gniod saw I ekil gnileef eb d’I“
”,ecin s’ti tub htap netaeb eht ffo s’tI“
.yrebbur erew sbmil ym lla ekil gnileef dna ,ytaews ,toh saw I
.seirc ym elffum ot ydob sih gnisu
”.yaw eht yb ,drarreG dlot I dna ,hO
.su woleb snedrag eht ot tuo dekool dna kcab denael ydoK
”?klat nac ew erehw ecalp teiuq a wonk uoy oD  .laeD“
.gnip railimaf a draeh I nehw liame ym dekcehc dah I   .laD   .llew er’uoy epoh I
”?sregnaR lartcepS ekiL
.dehgis dna rethgit em degguh ydoK
.somsoc eht ni tfirda acro na
,truh dna ,desufnoc ,tespu
?em htiw trats t’nac I fi esle enoemos evol I nac woh ,naem I
.detacilpmoc yrev eb nac hcihw ,fleseno ot
,era ew ohw wonk ew nac woh neht
;ekatsim a ekam ot gniog htob erew ew kniht I
,lla ti tuoba deracs er’uoy tuB“
.resolc em dellup eh tub mih morf yawa dehcnilf I
?eeffoc ro etib a teg
.ydoK em llac tub ,eniF“
.enif saw I dias dna deil I
.gniniart ro semag ni deneppah stnemom esoht yllausU
.maerd revef yag a sa pu mih derujnoc ylpmis dah I dna tniop siht ta laer neve saw eh fi rednow ot gnitrats saw em fo traP
,dah I sa drah sa ti gnihsup rof em ta yrgna ydob ym leef dluoc I
,enohp ym ot revo dehcaer dna esolc rood moorhtab eht draeh I  ”!sesimorp oN“
.ydoK ta decnalg I
.elttil a teef ym delffuhs dna taorht ym deraelc I
,fles laer ruo eb ot ytinutroppo eht nevig neeb reven evah ew fI
.em wonk yllaer t’ndluow ma I ohw gnidih elihw tem I enoyna taht erugif I
.niaga ti yrt ot tnaw osla I tub
.rehtruf denetsil dna ytsenoh sih fo ewa ni saw I teY
neht…daeh sih detlit dna em ta ylwols deknilb flow ehT  ”?ecivdA“   ”.ecivda
”.srettam tahw s’taht dna ,gniyrt era elpoeP
!taht morf tsuj dehctiwt kcoc ym ,lleH
,sgnileef srehto htiw hcuot ni tog ohw enoemos ton yletinifed saw eh ,saw eh sa dneirf a layol dna doog sA
.nur gnol eht ni sdneirf ym eb llits dluow tlas rieht htrow enoyna tub ,tsrif ta drah eb dluow ti taht derugif I  .tuo
.htap thgir eht no m’I ekil leef I tub
”?ti seod ,nrop ni taht ekil kool t’nseoD“
!reeb gnizama siht evah yehT
.tenretni eht no sgniht yllis tsuJ“
?ecaps em gnivig eh saW
.ecivda emos esu dluoc I
,nac uoy erofeb tuB .era uoy ohw
.meht tnorfnoc ot diarfa oot saw I tub ,ereht erew sngis eht
.gnikrims dna keehc sih gnison ,delims I ”,rerettalF“
”?ma I ohw htiw yppah ton m’I fi kcab em evol ot enoyna tcepxe I nac woH
.buc a sa wohs eht devol dah I
!rekcol eht ni ti tup ,lleW“
.redluohs ym dnuora mra na tup dna em ot txen nwod tas dna revo emac eh yllautnevE  .yrc em tel eH
.yllufyalp ti gnippin ,rae ym ot revo daeh sih denael dna desaet ydoK  ”.yllaD ,rof ezigolopa ot gnihtoN“
”.eman tsal ym etah I
.taht sa emac I os ,dekil enoyreve tahw s’taht derugif I
”?ynnuf os s’tahW“  .deknilb eH
taht…haeY“   ”.taert yM“
.ti…tuoba klat ot tnaw uoy ti ekat I“  .denettalf srae siH
”?siht tuoba enoyna ot klat t’now uoy…llew…tsuj I“
yeht…era yeht esle revetahw ro ,ib ro ,yag era ohw wonk I syug tsoM“
?rof uoy esaet ylbaborp dluow sdneirf ruoy taht dik a erew uoy nehw gnihtemos ekil reve uoY“
eno siht piks esaelp
.yako saw I erus ekam ot dna gnihsal eugnot a em evig ot edisa em dellup neve dah hcaoc eht dna ylroop enod dah I  .nwod maet eht tel I
.taht ekil gnihtemos ro emirc a fo tegrat eht eb dluoc I fi ro ,kniht thgim elpoep tahw tuoba deirrow elttil a m’I ,naem I
.tnecs sih ni ehtaerb dluoc I
”.yllautca ,doog sdnuos
,naem I…wonk t’nod I“
.tuo pop daeh s’ydoK ees ot emit ni tsuj dehgual dna detrons I   .rethciR
thguac eH  .revo llef tsomla eh doots eh nehw dna pu tas eH
.somsoc eht ni tfirda acro na ,iaK yb daeR
dna…ekil s’ti tahw ees yllaer ot tnaw I
.ti ot desu gnitteg era tsom tub
”.naem I ,slrig htiW
,ecaf ym ssorca gnikcilf erew seye sih dna ,trams saw flow ehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.etarepsed dednuos I
.ksam diputs taht gniraew fo derit m’I
,tsrif ta dekcohs saw eH“  ”?ti ekat eh d’woH“
”?dekil uoy elpoep htiw ti erahs t’ndluoc tub gnihtemos yojne ot deticxe erew uoy nehw leef uoy ekam ti d’woH“   .deddon I
.citehtap dnuos t’ndid I epoh I
.rehtegot seceip eht tup ot gnitrats saw ydoK   ”?drah ti saw…tuB“
tuo emoc tsrif tsum uoy
.flesym neve ton ,enoyna ot taht dettimda reven dah I
,em ot gniklat elbuort evah syug emoS
.flesruoy ni edirp evaH  .ti etarbeleC
?yag er’uoy fi wonk uoy oD“
?yug a htiw emit tsrif ruoy saw tahT“
.emit siht toN
.buc ynit a neeb dah I ecnis yrc em ees nam rehtona tel dah I emit tsrif eht saw ti tuB
”…dah syawla I kniht I…erom yug eht ta gnikool saw dna nrop pu dekool yllautca I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.dnah ym htiw ti derevoc dna drawrof ecaf ym tup I
.derewsna I ”,gnihtoN“
.yag gnieb fo diarfa ton m’I
”,hcum toN“  ”?pu s’tahW  .laD“
uoy…rorroh lacirotsih dnim t’nod uoy epoh I
.rekcol sih fo tuo gab sih gniknay
.esle enoyreve rof ysae neeb ev’dluoW
gnihtemos eb ot gnidneterp enoemos htiw kaeps ton dluow
:flesti fo dna ni detacilpmoc ton tub ,drah si srehto ot tuo gnimoC
.sgniht lufrednow hcus em dlot reve dah efil ym ni eno oN  .gnikahs saw I
.nam a htiw xes tuoba gniklat tuoba nepo os gnieb ydoK ta knip denrut srae yM   ”.yug a htiw sa yaw emas eht toN
.eb ot em detnaw enoyreve etelhta tcefrep eht eb ton ot yako saw ti taht dna
.moor ruoy fo tuo dedolpxe fo dnik I
.yako m’I ,haey…tub
.em ta yrgna yllufthgir saw eH
.daeh sih denilcni neht dna deknilb eH
tub etamitni t’nsaw tI
.dluoc I sa thgit sa ydoK otno gnidloh ,seye ym no mrof ot detrats taht sraet kcab dleh I dna dereviuq waj yM
ton…tsuj dna bif a ro eil a gnillet saw I ekiL
…gnirednow saw I“ ,deksa I ,htaerb
,rae ym htiw gniyalp tpek ydoK tub ,rehtegot kcab flesym tup ot gniyrt saw I  .dnah ym htiw eson dna seye ym depiw dna delffins I sa dias I ”,selkcit tahT“
.gnorw saw tahw deksa dna ecitcarp retfa em derenroc neve drarreG
,em dleh dna gnorts saw eH
,taht retfa sruoh wef a rof peels ot tnaw I“
.em deksa etamdeb ym
emac hturt eht fi em tuoba erac t’ndluow ohw elpoep rehto rof ton m’I gnihtemos eb ot tnaw t’ndid I
.elahxe wols a tuo tel dna em ta gnilims saw ydoK    .em morf hgual a gniward ,hcnilf ti gnikam
.taht yas ot detnaw tsuj I ,yawynA
.mih no gniyal flah dna nwo sih neewteb gel a gnikrow
.eromyna edih ot tnaw t’ndid I“
.htaerb ym hctac ot dedeen I   .retaL skeeW owT
”.tsenoh gnieb
:niatrec rof siht wonk I tuB  .laD ,ysae eb ll’ti taht yas t’nac I“
.tuo saw ,saw ti revetahw ,terces yM
.levan sih dnuora dna hcamots sih no demrof diuqil fo loop enillatsyrc a htiw
.ereh tis tsuj t’ndluoc I dezilaer I ,erom gniyrc dna revognuh gnieb fo yad a retfA  2 fo 2 traP ,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb
.mih ees ot tnaw t’ndid I thguoht ylbaborp eH
.ti rof gnireffus eno eht eb dluow I
.morf emoc dah ew loop eht morf enirolhc fo tnecs tniaf eht htiw ,ysdoow dna mraW
.nam nigriv-tsop ,duorp a saw I
.esle gnihton dna etelhta olop retaw eht ees ot detnaw uoy thguoht I
.em dehctaw dna denworf ydoK
,eno taht welb I os
”?eivom a ees og ot tnaw uoy
.yks gninekrad eht ta pu dekool dna tib elttil a delkcuhc I
.taht fo egatnavda gnikat neeb ev’dluow I dna ydaer ton erew uoy
.eeffoc sih deppis eh sa dias ydoK
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.deb moor mrod ,llams eht no flow eht ot txen nwod deppolf I
,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb ”edirP gniksamnU“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     ”.nom’C  .yllaD
.gnorw tlef gnihtyrevE
.dedda ydoK ”,ykcits dnA“  ”.tew…siht
.rewohs eht ni em nioj neht dna tsrif pu denaelc teg em teL“  .moorhtab eht ta dekool dna dehgual ydoK   ”.hcaoC
.yllufhsab ,delkcuhc dna flesmih
”.enoemos ot klat ot deen yllaer I  .esaelP  .yltcerid
.detca I woh rof yrros m’I
”?yako klaw ot elba eb annog uoY“   ”.taht
.tew…siht eb ot xes detcepxe reven I“
.ecaf sih no nrecnoc tub gnihton dah ohw ydoK ta dekool dna daeh ym detfil I tuB
.laD ,llet ot yrots ym toN“
.detesolc deyats yletulosba ev’dluoc I“
.eromyna ma I ohw fo diarfa ton m’I
,onnuI…ot tnaw uoy oD  .yeH“
.mih ot yas ot sgniht emos dah I ,llitS