.knird sih fo pis rehtona koot dna em ta revo dekool xof elbram ehT .dias I
.yltfos dias selrahC ”,t’nod uoy fi erom truh lliw tI“
”,ailuJ ,enecs cilbup rehtona tey edam eH“ - ”.ailuJ dnif ll’I
.frut ymene no gnieb fo esnes taht tlef I
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
”,neslO .rM tuoba snrecnoc sah ehs esuaceb em derih ehS“
.dettut taots eht ”,selttob ytpme eht wolloF“
”,etauqedani leef stseug rehto eht ekam ot edur s’ti wonk uoy ,selrahC woN“
.moor eht fo edis eht ot doots
.ecnis reve tsomla gnitad
,mih dleh dna deb eht no tas I
.peekrab eht ot dias I
.notruB sM fo erugif eht tuo kcip tuoba tsuj ot elba saw I
.retaW .taht tsuj saw tI
,noitisop siht ni nam a neeb dah I ,lleH
”?neslO lledneW fo eman eht yb nam a wonk ot neppah t’ndluow uoY“
.detibihxe uoy taht uoy lanoitcif eht fo aedi eht dekil yeht tseb tA“
.elbarenluv tlef I ,enog selrahC htiW
rotagitsevni etavirp a derih rethguad ruoY“ .ylmrif dias I ”?yrros m’I“
”.mih ot desoporp d’I retfa detrats ti esuaceb ,egairram eht htiw od ot s’ti emussa ylno nac I tuB .t’nsah eh on ,oN“
revewoh edisnwod ehT
er’uoY“ .niaga mih dloh ot esolc gnippets ,dias I
– ”.ot deen ew nehw edih ot woh wonk lla eW“
”,reh truh reven I“
”?tuo dnif seilimaf s’ailuJ dna enim fi dnA“
”.sriatspu moordeb a ni eb yam eH .od I ,riS ,seY“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.niaga mih gnissik ,dedda I ”.thginoT“
.xof dlo eht ecaf ot denrut dna sdrawno ailuJ derutseg I
.lortnoc yeht ,no ediced yeht ,etatcid yeht elor a ,efil rieht ni elor a yalp ot uoy tnaw yehT
.deddon dna htaerb a koot I
.ereht erew ew emit tsal mlif fo tuo mih nar eW ?os taht sI“
krad eht ni sessylU peek nac rotciV fi
”?ecalp eht tuoba wonk uoy od tahW“
,detrons neht dna depsag eH .deilper I
.enizagam eht pu dekcip dna moor eht otni kcuns I
.dias I ”..ecalp refas on s’ereht neht
.ydit yllufthguoht ton ,ydit yllacinilC
.noitcivnoc htiw gnihtyna od mih was I emit tsrif eht ,detsisni lledneW ”,reh truh lliw tI“
”?ekil kool eh seod tahW“
.eusrup ot kciuq dna paehc ylriaf gnieb dna ti deen ohw elpoep gnipleh
,selrahC ta revo dekool I nehT
.gnidliub eht edisni erew uoy ecno ylno
.eciton ot em ta gniralg ysub oot saw eh tub
.eye eht ni daed em dekool ehS ”.oN“
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“yojne esaelP
”.dnah fo thgiels tsuJ“
.knurd saw lledneW
.tpurretni ot ytinutroppo eht gnikat ,dias I
.t’nsaw ti tub ,ereht saw enizagam eht fo egap deppir eht fi ees ot taes eht dekcehc I elihw pu lledneW dekcip selrahC
.egnahc ot moordeb eht otni derepmacs neht ,niaga em dessik eH .deerga selrahC
.moorllab eht otni tuo llaw eht sdrawot derutseg eH
.niav ni saw ti dezilaer ylkciuq eh tub ,dehcaorppa ew sa su morf yawa elffuhs ot deirt eH
…si seilimaf ruo gnipacsE“ .dias ehS
.epacse na yfitsuj dna ,meht esaeppa pleh ot gniog osla saw lledneW ot egairram yM“
”.efil ruoy ekat ot gniog er’uoy taht deirrow s’ehS“
,erofeb reh morf nees ton d’I noissergga htiw daeh sih fo kcab eht ta deralg ailuJ
”.pihsnoitaler rieht dnem dna yrt ot uoy derih rethguad ym taht erawa m’I“ .delwocs eH
”,nac uoy sa eliforp a wol sA“
.detfihs erats evissap siH
”?meht no seicnedneped yna evah uoy oD“
.moor eht dehcaorppa I
.ti hsinif t’ndluoc tub ,ecnetnes eht nageb eh
.enips ym pu rettulf ot nageb cinap a tniop siht tA
.mih ot kcab nehT
.erom gniknird neeb s’eH“
.ylevisiced dna ylmrif dias ehS ”.ton yletulosbA“ ”?tneloiv neeb
,tpmetnoc htiw em ta dekool notruB rM
.sgnidne yppah dah taht lufdnah a tnuoc ylno dluoc I taht si
.nwod tas dna em deknaht ehS ”.taes a ekat
”,pu tilps ot si lledneW etacol ot yaw tseb eht kniht I“
.detnaw yeht tahw enoyreve evig ot em rof nam laedi eht ekil demees lledneW dnA
.niaga em gnissik ,dennirg selrahC ”,esaelp hO“
.yltfos dias selrahC
…tub nam lufrednow ,ylevol a s’eH
”?htiw revo ti teg nac eW“
- .neslO lledneW dna
”.efas erehwemos mih teg ew ,nehT
.gnorw ,yllacinhcet ,ton saw siht taht flesym dnimer ot dah ylraluger I .dias I
naht reh gnillet ton em yb erom truh s’ehs fI“
;sgnirehtag yteicos hgih otni erutnevda tsrif ruo t’nsaw sihT
…yrev ton s’tI“ ,dias eh ”,seY“
.derepsihw yehT .deralg elpoeP
.kcab dekconk sknird owt ,tem sessalg owT
.MP3 ta ronaM esuohdliuG ta devirra eW
.derised eb ot ton erew thguac gnitteg esiwrehto ro mih gnikoopS
.deksa eh ”?yalbmerT rM“
”?tnediserp eht ekiL“ .dias eh
seigolohtna owt ni derutaef neeb sah ohw
”?egairram taht ni gnieb rof
.seye ym deworran I .dias eh
”?uoy htiw ailuJ ot ekops ew fi dnim uoy dluoW“
.dehgis I ”,lanoitome yreV
.em hguorht ylsuoiraciv egairram lufsseccus a evah ot stnaw eh ekil leef
,renroc a dnuor liat a ees ot emit ni tsuj
.denrut eh ,yltpurbA
”?egairram eht ffo llac ot deksa eh saH“
.htaerb sih rednu ti derepsihw eH
.deksa selrahC ”?nalp eht s’tahW“
”,ailuJ“ ”?esnes nees yllanif uoy evah rO“ .deksa eH
,nosaer emos rof tuB .ecalp siht rof dnarb tnatropmi na saw ti ,saw ti revetahW
dias I ”,notruB sM“
.detaeper eb t’ntsum taht tseuqer ylohnu ehT
.siht ekil esuoh ronam tsav a ni tnemanruot ssehc a deyalp ecno dah selrahC
…er’eW “ .ronaM eht ot pu derutseg selrahC ”,ereh ni er’ew elihW“
.dnah a gnidnetxe ,dias I ”,seY“
.mih ni ro em ni lausunu taht dnif t’ndid I“ .yltalf ,dias ehS
.srood edis eht gnitcepsni detrats I ,ynoclab eht no pU
,elkcuhc ot ton yrt ot pil sih gnitib
.deplug neht ,deredduhs eH .dias I
”,notruB ailuJ fo tseuqer no ereh m’I ,yalbmerT rotciV“
.dias eh ”,ti snwo rehtaf reH .ronam esuohdliuG ni ereh ailuJ htiw evil I“ .deksa I
”,reh truh t’nevah uoY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
eno siht piks esaelp
nepo dleh ,smoor rehto otni srood erew sedis yrev eht ta ynoclab eht htaeneB
.redluohs sih revo em ta ezag ot gnisuap neht ,moordeb eht ecaf ot dnuora gninrut
.knurd eb ot ylekiL .s’02 ylraE .xof elbraM“
,ozirraC yb uoy rof daer
;nosaer eht citehtap woh ro
”,uoy pleh ot elba eb thgim I fi gnirednow saw I“
-- .moor tnelis-won eht ssorca deklaw dna denrut neht ,kcab pets a koot eH
.su ta desuap neht ,hguorht elpoep derehsu eH
”.xes ni detseretni ylraluger ton m’I hguohT“
.mih dnif uoy nehw suoicsnoc llits s’eh taht epoh dnA“
trihs sserd kcalB .ruf elbram sih hctam ot tius etihw a ni desserd saw eH
.yrassecen yletulosba saw ti sselnu yticapac cilbup a ni
.sfeirb sih fo tnorf eht nwod wap ym deffuts
...ruo fo serutcip erom emos teg
.yllabrev dnopser t’ndid I
dna llaw taht ta dekool I .elttab a ton ,raw a rof ni saw I taht
.eromyna ton m’I taht flesym dednimer dna
.dias xof yM ”.snaem suoibud …rednu deriuqca ,stcafitra fo noitcelloc tsav a sah renwo eht si sdroW“
”?…si eno sulp ruoy dnA“
.cinap ot mih tnaw t’nod I
.elcyc noitneverp eht ni llits erew ew tnaem hcihW
”,tegrof ot dnabsuh a fo gnimoceb
…tsuj eH .tahw tuoba em llet t’now eH“ .dias ehS ”,seirc eH“
I dna tuo devom I retfa tsuj detarapes rehtaf dna rehtom yM
,dedda selrahC ”,degnahc teg retteb d’I“
.eniw fo ssalg a gnikat ,dias I ”,uoy knahT“
,lledneW trofmoc dna ereh niamer dluoc uoy fi
”?mih ot desoporp uoY“ .deknilb I
dna enim tsniaga kcab spih sih desserp
”neslO lledneW gnivaS :ni yalbmerT rotciV“
”.morf meht tog yeht erehw ksa
”?mih nwonk ev’uoy emit eht tuohguorht tcatnoc lauxes yna ni degagne nam siht dna uoy evaH“
.retaw naht rekciht si doolb
.repsihw a ta ,dessih eH
”.edicius tcepsus I“
”,oot daor siht nwod neeb ev’ew esuaceB“
.deilper ehs ”,taht fo erawa edam neeb ev’I“
slliks fo tes ralucitrap a evah uoy revewoh
.dnomaid a pota decalp ksam a gnilbmeser
…tlef gnidliub siht ni devil ailuJ dna lledneW taht noitalever eht tuoba gnihtemoS
,woh wonk I yaw ylno eht uoy knaht d’I“
- .desolc peek t’ndluoc yeht terces a saw ti rO
cebeuQ ot kcab thgir liat yepirts ruoy ylf yllanosrep lliw I ro ,nam taht gniyrram fo tuo rethguad ym klat lliw uoY
,ti sdrawot dedaeh I
”?rethguad ym rof tseb s’tahw wonk uoy kniht yllaer uoY“
.elbacilppa tseb syawla ton si rohpatem tesolc ehT
.dehgis eH ”?sdneirf tsuj
.stsacdop ruoy
”,ees I“ ”-dna daeha og tsuj d’I rO
”?tuoba klat ot gnihtemos
”.pordsevae ot ton hguone etilop ti dnif dluow uoy kniht ot ekil dluow I dna noissucsid tnatropmi na gnivah era I dna rethguad yM .tiaw nac eH“
”?ylimaf notruB eht morf htlaew eht fo emos tirehni ot gnipoh erew uoY“
.htaerb gnol a werd eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,derepsihw lledneW
,fles eslaf a gnimrofrep fo
.em depacse ti ,ereht dna neht tub ,egap siht no saw nam hcihw rebmemer dluoc I niarb ym ni erehwemoS
”,gnivah s’eh tahw evah ll’I“ ”.esaelp ,knird A“
”,hturt eht ailuJ lleT“
”.ot sah ydobemos sseug I“ .deggurhs I
.tug ym ni derrits gnileef gninekcis A
”?taht si yhW“ ”.paehc ton
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.flesym tcelloc ot tnemom a koot dna yawa klaw mih dehctaw I ”.mih
”,enim fo dneirf a s’eh ,rednaxelA selrahC“
”.erutuf ym ot od ll’elpoep eseht tahw wonk t’nod I
”?eliforp wol a niatniam ot tseb eht rof s’ti spahreP“
.elpmaxe rieht dewollof I .eil ot woh em thguat yehT“
”.ot demialc reven I“
.truoC eht ni etoyoC ruoy ,ozirraC yb daeR
.wolf dworc mumixam wolla ot
,deerga eh ”,od naC“
.yltnecer gnihtyna detpmetta t’ndah eh taht tnedifnoc ylbanosaer saw I ,mih morf noitcaer taht htiW
ot dah d’I srentrap suoiverp morf egnahc emoclew a edam ti gnihtyna fI
.dias selrahC ”.htiw nigeb ot uoy devol reven
.nam tfard eht ot deil neve I .ssob ym ot ,droldnal ym oT .sdneirf ym ot ti tuoba deil I nehT .meht ot ti tuoba deil tsuj I tsrif tA
”,evol ym ,uoy rof tseb eht ylnO“
ekil saw siht tahw derebmemer I
.uoy ot gnineppah s’tahw ees nac ehS“
”?ssem elbirroh siht fo tuo htob su teg oT ?thgir ti ekam oT“
.dluoc eh sa drah sa tsuj deirc
.emoh ruo ni oiloftrop ralucitrap siht fo ypoc a saw ereht niatrec saw I tcaf nI .nrop yaG .nroP
era uoy ohw revo etah ot snrut evol esohw elpoeP“
,enecs a gnisuac saw yrtne fo lained ruo dna
.os did I sa rebmun moor eht fo eton a gnikam ,moor eht detraped neht ,tekcop tekcaj ym ni ti deffuts I
.ecnegilid eud gniod s’ehS
.elpoep fo spmulc neewteb delffuhs syart sknird htiw srevreS
.srehto eht enola tel
:ksam a fo kaeps ot retteb eb thgim tI
...ot pu s’ailuJ htrae no tahw tuo krow nac enoyna fi dna
dna frut ymene no saw I taht gnizilaeR
.siht ekil saw I dezilaer I nehw
.ruf erab sih revo sdnah ym gninnur dna kcab sih tsniaga flesym gnisserp ,yas I
.yksir saw dnif ot enoyna rof ereh tuo enizagam siht gnivaeL
.dias ehS ”.yalbmerT rM ,elpoep dnik ton …er’yehT“
.selrahC dleh eh dna
.tol gnikrap eht otni denorepahc erew eW
,moorllab egral eht fo renroc eno ni ailuJ derehtag dah sessylU
,derepsihw eH ”?I t’ndid ,eno taht rof pu uoy tes yllaer I“ .t’ndluow eh hsiw I hguoht
ssecnirp derevil-ylil ,neknurd taht enod si gnihtemos sselnu taht snrecnoC“
?em hO“ ”.ereh revo ylenol elttil a kool uoY“ .dias I
.enola gnieb derebmemer
,yna nepo dna yrt ot detatiseh I .meht no sngis yna dah meht fo enoN
.htgnerts sih denommus lledneW
.esacriats eht fo pot eht raen rodirroc a nwod noitommoc a raeh dluoc I ,kcab denrut I sA
.selrahC dna em neewteb tas saw eh taht os rab eht ta taes a koot I
.niaga deretlaf ezag siH
”.ekat ot esnepxe eht etiuQ“ .worb a desiar I
.elims yrw a htiw detaeper ,selrahC ,xof yM ”?ronaM esuohdliuG“
rehtegot su fo riap eht knil ot tnaw t’ndid I tub ,niaga reh gnihcaorppa deredisnoc I
,ytilauxes s’lledneW tuoba tcerroc si noitiutni ym fI“
”?ytiledifni tcepsus uoy oD“ ”.seirc
.taht tuoba ton tuB
”,hturt eht ailuJ lleT“
.em ot kcab nehT .oot selrahC ot detfihs yltpurba erats siH
,neesnu gniniamer fles eurt eht ni ton semoc ti fo mrah eht fo hcum rof
.ekil dekool ti tahw rebmemer ot gniyrt
.ynoclab eht htaenrednu
.lufthgisni ssel dna retnulb tub ,s’ailuJ sa wolley sa tsuj seye ,redlO
nirg gib a
,ot hsiw ton od uoy fi ti rewsna ot deen ton od uoy ,noitseuq lanosrep a uoy ksa ot ekil d’I“
.llah niam eht morf ni elpoep werd noos ,moor eht ni elpoep fo noitnetta eht gniward tsuj htiw nageb tahW
ot erus eb ll’I ,gnidliub eht morf detceje eb ot deen reve ew fI“ .deddon I
”.si ti kniht I sa prahs sa t’nsi noitiutni ym sseug I neht…gnorw m’I fI“
.tsaot ot ssalg eht gnisiar ,dias I ”,htlaeh doog oT“
.enizagam a tas deb eht no tub
.moordeb a ot rood nepo na dna
,knird a gnippis saw dna sserd eulb gnol a gniraew saw ehS
”.reh truh t’ndid I em llet esaelP
,elpoep fo ytpme eb ot demees ti ,edisni gnireeP
,ralucitrap ni dnA
.sselepoh dna sselpleh sihT
.elpoep fo sgnorht eht ni srumel dlo eht nees dah I nrows evah dluoc I ,neht dna won yrevE
.em rof rewsna na evah t’ndid notruB sM ,emit tsrif eht roF
.desaet eH ”?raewrednu ym ni yats I referp d’uoy sselnU“
,edisni og ot pu gninil elpoep dna somil ni ffo deppord gnieb elpoep erew erehT
rednaxelA selrahC erew ereht tas dnA
”.gniklat dna gnitibahoc
…neeb s’eh yltnecer
meht evig yllaer …wonk uoY“
.tseug a ot ylnezarb os ti trulb ot gnilliw saw reltub a fi terces nepo na erew selbuort s’neslO rM demees tI
.tlah a ot em dnirg did sihT ”.seuqcaJ wonk I“
ruf ym fo tuo muc ruoy teg ot sega sekat ti tub
,dneirfyob ym tem ev’uoy ees I“ .nageb I ”,lledneW“ .trats doog a saw ti dna ti knard lledneW tuB
”,ees I“ .t’nsaw rehto eht ,oobat saw eno taht tsuJ .sdneirf dna
”.eno sulp a dna flesruoy rof noitavreser a ni tup I lufesu saw ti esac nI
.pu mih rebos ,pets tsriF
.tnedicni cilbup yrev a saw tI
-- ”.snoitpo rehto esoht morf trapa uoy tes hcihw
”?eb dluow uoy dnA“
.rab a saw roolf dnuorg eht no nwod ,ynoclab eht etisoppO .reteiuq dna
.deksa eh ”?od I nac tahW“
”.uoy htiw drow a sdeen lledneW“
.reh deppots sessylU tub ,em wollof ot devom ehS .dias I
mih dleh selrahC sa tsuj
”neslO lledneW gnivaS
.lla ta noitome trevo hcum tuohtiw ailuJ
hhhhu hO“ .em ot kcab neht
.em gnihcaorppa ,dias eh ”,yteicos fo rebmem gnidnatspu na si rehtaf ruoy ,sediseb dnA
.sknird fo yart rehtona htiw ydob s’xof elbram eht tsap gniklaw
.ta kool ot raeb t’ndluoc I taht nirg A .dennirg lledneW
”.tuo dnif enoyna tel naht ereht deid evah rehtar d’I tuB
”.sliar eht ffo
.deksa I ”?yaw tahw nI“
”?lasoporp eht ot sey dias uoy yhw taht sI“
”,yaw taht yats ot uoy ekil d’ew tub ,eruS“
.moor eht dnuora detrad seye reH
,ailuJ ot sgnileef sih timda nac lledneW fi tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
dna redluohs s’xof ym ni ecaf sih deirub lledneW ”.uoy pleh su teL
.tius paehc a ni moordeb eht morf degreme xof yM
nac yrraL spahreP .yaw etilop eht si telfael A“
.pots ot rehtob t’ndid I
,aingisni na dah sllaw eht no roced eht fo emoS
.reh truh ot detnaw reven I“ em
;segatnavda rieht dah yeht ,em roF .nezod a emid
a era sesac detaler-ytiledifni dna ytiledifni ,evitceted etavirp eht roF
.secalp fo sdnik eseht ni nees gnieb nees eb ot dedeen sa yenom hcum sa dneps dluow rehtaf dna rehtom yM
.dat a pils ot demees erusopmoc
.llah eht fo dne eht ta tfel eht ot enog dah liat ehT
”,hturt eht ailuJ llet ot evah ot gniog er’uoY“
.ew erew oS .gniyrc saw eH
.truoC eht ni etoyoC ruoy
.llaw eht ta derats I .dias I
.spuc eht dna slewot eht no aingisni esoht fo erom erew erehT
.evael ot seog eh sa tcejretni I ”-gniht eno ,hO“
.lledneW etacol ot si evitcejbo tsriF“
.dias ehs ”,tcerroc s’tahT“
.elzzum sih no
.roolf elbram eht otno delbmut dna deppirt lledneW ,did I sA .teef ym ot tpael I .nar eH
.delworg eH ”!rethguad ym gniyrram eb ot gniog si
”?reh truh t’now taht od I nac tahW“
”,yenom eht yltrap dna ,taht yltraP“
”?regnol yna noitailimuh siht hguorht em tup ot gniog uoy erA“
.tnatropmi saw gniklat mih gnipeeK .detpurretni I
.roolf eht ta ylknalb derats eH .deunitnoc I
.”krow“ sa os gniod yfitsuj ot elba emit tsrif eht rof ,ti hguorht dekcilf I
.moor eht dnuora gniklaw nageb I
.emit ni mih dehcaer d’ew tuB
.retiaw eht ot kcab denrut I .dias I
.eromyna yenom rof gniyrrow eb t’ndluow ew
,eb-ot-dnabsuH“ .dias ehS
”.kcolc eht tsniaga pu tahwemos er’ew dna
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
”.riaffa na evah did
.moorllab nepo egral a saw deretne ew moor ehT
.wonk dluow enoyrevE
,selrahC“ .pu doots I ”.yakO“
.moor nepo egral rehtona gnikoolrevo ynoclab rehtona otni em tes sihT
.htaerb gnol a werd I
.teiuq a ot moor eht fo bubbuh eht gnignirb
.odexut a ni revaeb a yb dedraug saw rood ehT
.deb eht yb nwod gnittauqs dna mih sdrawot gnippets
.deil I ”,nrecnoc ruoy etaicerppa I“
,em ot gnihtyna naem t’ndid tI
.tuo naelc nroT .gnissim egap a saw erehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.rettalp a gnidloh ,em erofeb doots taots A ”?riS ,knird A“
”.meht ot emoh kcab og t’nac I ,draknurd a m’I wonk stnerap yM“
”.sdneirf tsuJ“ .ylkeem deddon I
”,won ti od nac eW“ ”.ti od ll’I …reh gnillet em yb
rethgirb saw sihT
”?eb ot elbail lledneW si erehW“
”?lativ si tnaw yeht gnihtyreve meht gnivig dnA“
.dias I ”,uoy knahT“
,selrahC neht ,em ta dekool eH
.ronaM esuohdliuG ta gnineve siht ytrap a gnidnetta er’eW“ .deksa I
.ti neddih lla evah su ekil elpoeP“
fi sa sehtolc paehc ruo ta gnikool ,delbmum recnuob eht
.sseldrager ti ksam t’ndluoc eH
”.tol a mih ekil I“
.kcurt imes a ekil lledneW tih ot demees drow ehT
esaelP“ .eciffo ym deretne xof der a sa
”.reh llet ot deen ll’uoy yletamitlu tub ,uoy pleh lliw eW“ .tsal ta dias I
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,esoht fo lla derolpxe I“
.yllamrof ylrevo spahrep ,dias I
.reh wollof ot detrats dna denrut I
.snoitavreser fo tsil sih ta nwod dekool neht ,su neewteb deralg recnuob ehT .dias I
.efil sih fo ridan ehT .su erofeb tas nam nekorb A
”,dnabsuh ym tuoba s’tI“
.deddon eH .deksa I
”.tseretni yramirp rieht saw taht mohw
.detacixotni saw eh elihw siht ekil nam nekorb a etagorretni ot raeb t’ndluoc I
.ylmrif tub ,yltfos dias ehS ”.snosaer ym evah I“
”.laed taerg a yfiralc dluow ti tub
.lohocla erom tey kcab kconk ot neek dna laivoj ton era detpmetta tsuj evah ohw elpoeP
.ti eusrup ot emit evah t’ndid I tub ,em ot ,ffo
.woleb moor eht ta nwod kool ot tnemom a koot I ,eton fo gnihton htiW
,taoctsiaw etihw ,stnap kcalb ,trihs kcalb ,mrofinu a dah yehT
.swap reh ta nwod dekool ehS .deborp I
.neppah ti tel dna deddon tsuj os ,tsiser ot sselrewop saw lledneW
.ecaf sih otno deraems elims lufwa na htiw ,deunitnoc sessylU
.ylmrif dias eh ”,retal uoy htiw kaeps lliw I“
.delims I ”,did uoY“
.eb-ot-dnabsuh reh fo ytefas eht no kcehc ot
.em ta elims ot deirt eH .deil eh
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.riaffa na dah ehs epoh tsuj d’I“
.htaerb a werd eH ”.seY“
”,notruB sessylU“ ”?eb dluow uoy dnA“
gnihtyreve did I“ .esraoh taorht sih ,derepsihw eh ”?tuo dnif enoemos did woH“ .daeh sih desiar yllanif xof elbram ehT
.niaga seye yarg esoht htiw em ta dekool eH
.dereffo I ”?notruB ailuJ“
”,nemeltneg gnineve dooG“
,niaga deksam noissergga ,deddon ailuJ
srehto yb desopmi dna detaerc
.seye yssalg ,yerg htiw em ta derats dna teef sih ot delbmuts eh ,htuom ym tfel noitseuq eht tnemom ehT
.mih ecaf ot ti denrut selrahC regnif a htiw dna daeh sih detfil xof elbram ehT
ytissecen eht ni tub
naht erom gnihtyna ro egairram a ni tseretni yna nwohs t’ndah eh
”?od uoy ekil gnitca uoy era yhw nehT“
,mret gnol ,nalp ruoy saw tahW“ ”.eromyna
.tnatropmi eb dluow ti gnizilaer mih tuohtiw os gnioD
.reh htiw enoyna evah ton did ehS
.derruls eh ”?uoy pleh I naC“
.tixe na rof gnikool saw eH .dias eh
,tuo steg drow eht nehW“
.niaga detalfed lledneW
.em kcolb ot devom xof der rehtona fo erugif eht tub ,wollof ot tnew I
.erofeb noitamrofni rof sgabmucs knurd ynam detagorretni dah I
”.uoy rof drocer wen a eb tsuM“
”?smoor edis esoht yrt dluoc uoy kniht uoy od ,sriatspu dna ynoclab eht ,ereh ni yrt ll’I“ .selrahC ot dias I
”,enif tsuj m’I …m’I hO
.ailuJ desaeler neht ,esion eht fo ecruos eht ot ylprahs daeh sih denrut xof dlo ehT
.moor eht dekoolrevo
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.denruter eciov lluf sih erofeb ,derepsihw eh
.em pots dluoc htuom ym erofeb detrulb I
…lledneW ;etagitsni ot dah I gnihtemos saw sihT
.fo liat eht denioj yltpmorp ew taht enil a
reh emit tsrif eht rof ,tcaf nI
.kcohs saw ti spahrep rO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.edisni saw lledneW fi neve
.niaga em truh ot gnitiaW .em gnihctaW
”,dnim t’nod uoy fi ,retaw A“
”.thginot enummoc eht gnitisiv eb ll’ew hcnuh a evah I ?secnamrofrep
,lufraF lacsaP yb
,rrup duol a evag selrahC
.hguoc duol a evag ehs
.yltnatcepxe em ta dekool ehS
”.t’now uoy dna t’ntsum uoY“ .ylmrif dias selrahC ”,on ,lledneW“
.dnuof eb ot ti detnaw enoemos ro ,ekatsim a rehtie saw tI .ees dluoc I taht tifeneb etaidemmi on htiw dnA .yksir yrev ,yreV
”,srehto ni ekil skool ti tahw wonk ot teg eW
”.boj ym gniod m’I
,moor eno siht tsuj saw taht dnA .tra enif a si
.dias sessylU ”,oot snrecnoc evah I“ .deilper I
”.selrahC
.maN‘ ni eid ot tnes eb ot kaew oot saw I
”neslO lledneW gnivaS :ni yalbmerT rotciV“
.dias eh ”,era uoy oS“
”.radar eht rednu yletelpmoc edils ot gninnuts oot raf
.oot dah ylerus yrraL ,dah selrahC
,nur uoy raf woh rettam oN
.ailuJ pleh su teL“
srevol htob erew eW
”.paehc t’nia ffuts doog eht dnA
,ylmrif derepsihw I
.eb ot su enigami yeht ohw fo
.skcals etihw dna eit der
.detaeper I dna selrahC
,yag m’I taht rehtiE
.dias ehS ”.esnepxe oN“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
”?dnatsrednu uoy od ,gnoleb uoy erehw
”,dootsrednU“ ”.uoy ta ssap a sekam eh fi desirprus eb t’ndluow I“
.tug ruoy ni thgir edalb efink hcni ytnewt a seirub taht elims fo dnik tahT
”.ti edih ot dluoc I
ta pu neht ,selrahC ta revo kool ot daeh sih gnitfil
.rotciV ,ylimaf morf yawa nur t'nac uoY“
”…gniyrram eb ot gniog m’I ,tcaf nI“
”,taht rof tekram eht ni …ton m’I
,tekcaj dna taoctsiaw etihw a htaenrednu
.dias xof ym ”,teiuq erehwemos uoy teg s’tel ,no emoC“
”.won hturt eht reh llet si od nac uoy gniht tseb eht dna yllautneve tuo ti krow lliw ehS
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.derepsihw selrahC ”,esaelP“
.gnidliub eht fo ecnartne eht ot dnuora deklaw dna rac eht tfel eW
”,derised eb ot …si tI“
.niaga pu ecaf sih dewercs xof dlo ehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.xof etihw eht dna flesym rof ,retaw fo sessalg owt nwod decalp namrab ehT
”.yppah seitrap htob ekam ot nac I tahw od ot mia dna notruB sM dna neslO rM htob htiw gnisiail ma I“
,ton dluoc eh nehW
.llits yltcefrep tis I
.moor eht otni flesmih degalfuomac d’eh ,ti wenk I erofeb dna ,dias xof ym
.mih ta gnikool tsuj delb I doG
taht ynoclab roolf tsrif eht ot pu del kcab eht ta sriats fo tes A
”.seil no tliub si pihsnoitaler eritne ruO .sraey rof reh ot gniyl neeb ev’I“
.yawyna emit eht ta ton
.sesserd lufroloc dna stius revlis dna yarg suoirav ni elpoep fo aes a ni tops ot ysae meht edam hcihw
,revo llef sessalg fo kcats egral a ,moor eht ssorca morF
.wap ym htiw elbat eht deppat I
.moordeb elttil ylgu ym ni dekcoL
”.noitseuq eht dehcaorb I oS
taht ylno ,hcum yas t’ndid ehS .gniddew eht retfa neppah dluow tahw rof nalp a dah ehS .saw ailuJ“
,pu depip taots eht ”,lledneW ylrae os knurd oS“
.sriats ynoclab eht sdrawot devom neht
.deb eht no pu gnittis dna selrahC morf gniliocnu ,dehgis lledneW
”.me‘ kcuf neht ,wohs egats elttil rieht niur ot hguone si nem gnissik uoy fI
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb
,niaga reh ta kool ot nrut dluoc sessylU erofeB
2791 ,tsuguA fo dr3   2 fo 1 traP
.gniddew eht ffo llac nac I ekil leef t’nod I“
”?tops eht si enummoc s’yrraL gnikniht er’uoy dnA“
.llac sessylU draeh I ”?yalbmerT rM“
,deddon neht ,tnemom a detiaw I
.doog netsil uoy dna ereh netsil uoY“ .ralloc eht yb em debbarg eH
I kniht d’yeht ,esrow ro
.dehcnilf eH .dias selrahC
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.detalfed neht ,desnet ydob reH
.pot eht fo tuo gnikop ylerab tsuj ,tekcop tekcaj edisni eht otni yltaen dedlof gnihtemos saw erehT
.em desaeler eh dna
,ksir lanosrep wol
tcepsus gnikool tuohtiw slaudividni ta skool doog gnitteg dna ,ereh ni elpoep fo sderdnuh erew erehT
eh saH“ ”.erom emoh morf yawa neeB
.letoh a ot ralimis rennam a ni ydit esiwrehto saw moor ehT
,rodirroc eht fo renroc eht dnuora traped nees d’I liat eht dewollof I ,ereh morF
.noitisop siht ni neeb d’ohw nem wenk I
.tluciffid eb dluow lledneW gnidniF
.ecnesse eht fo saw emit taht gnileef elbirroh ,elbirroh a dah I
.eson sih hguorht tuo ti decrof neht ,htaerb gnol a werd eH
neeb evah ew dna 0791 fo llaf eht ni mih tem I .lledneW si eman siH .yas dluohs I
”.stseug demeetse hcus fo tnorf ni ,emoh ruo nI“
.ni su tel yltnatculer dna edis eno ot deppets eh
.yrtne ruo yfilauqsid ot yaw a dnif ot gniyrt
.cebeuQ ni pu gniworg tlef dah I ekil tsuJ
.deirram eb ot em stnaw rehtaf ym hcum woh wonk I“
.dias ehS ”,yllaer toN“
”?rollesnuoc a ro tsipareht a ot detius erom rettam a eb thgim siht ekil smees ti …tub em evigroF“