,ti htiw bom eht fo srebmem suoirav kcab gnitaeb saw dna riahc a pu dekcip dah recnuob eht ,rood eht dehcaer ew nehW
.htiw gnikrow saw ehs ohw wonk t’ndid I tub ,ailuJ ot mih denruter evah dluoc eW
tsuj m’I“ .dias I ”.haey hO“
.rehto eht gnikat dna mih ot eno gnidnah
.shgiht ym pu rednaw ot detrats swap siH
.niaga detrats lledneW ”,ailuJ“
”.lufituaeb er’uoY“
”?reeuq yllufssilb
.secilpmocca owt daH
.delrans xof yM ”!gnimoc gnikcuf ti dah hctib a fo noS“ ”!tohs su evah
yllaer uoY ?lledneW rof tsuj siht htiw em depleh uoY“ ”.emit gnol
?yltnecer ailuJ morf draeh uoy evaH“
.truoC eht ni etoyoC ruoy ,ozirraC yb daeR
.esuoh ruo dnif ylbaborp dluoC“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
…doof gnikooc ,sehtolc gniriaper ,sgniht gnidnem ,ffuts gnidliub ebyam ,gnimraf ebyaM
,skcuhs wA“ .rehtegot su fo eerht eht revo dekool eh dna mih desaeler selrahC
.mih ssik ot gnitrats
.dennirg eH ”.revoL“
”,noslO lledneW .lledneW
.elihw a rof rehto hcae dleh ew dna
niaga uoy knaht tsum I ,os dnA“
.nwod gniyl ti ekat t’now I
”,tib riaf a pu em gnirebos neeb ev’yehT
ehT“ .llaw eht dnoyeb morf emac tI
.deremmats I ”.uoy ot emas eht yas dluoc …I“
”.etuc er’uoy syas eh semitemoS“
,lledneW detacol selrahC dnabsuh sih dna rotciV .notruB ailuJ fo eb-
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.lliw eh erus m’I“
.ffits ylbakatsimnU .eson ot esoN .spal s’rehto hcae ni tub-lla erew ew ,tniop siht tA
.nosrep taht fo noisrev rehto denigami na fo ksam a yb tub
elpoep reeuq yltnarbiv ,ylnepo nezod wef a htiw evil lledneW gnittel dna ereht noitadommocca gnipeels elpma saw erehT
.hcterts yna yb motsuc gnilaeppanu na toN
.selrahC ot txen taes a koot I
.lla su deflugne ecneloiv rof tsul eht
”.thgiarts m’I kniht ot gnitrats era elttaeS ni kcab elpoep eht ,wonk uoy ,luferac eb ot evah I“ .dias I
.ti morf yawa lledneW peek ot evah dluow enoemos dna
.semit fo tseb eht fo
- .ria niht otni dehsinav dah xof esiw eht ,noisufnoc dna soahc eht lla nI
.delims eH ”.did I sey ,seY“
.tsal ta derepmihw eH
,meht rof kool t’ndid I
.enips ym pu revihs gnisaelp
”?tsurt ot gniog eh saw esle ohW .etats notgnihsaW ni eye etavirp reeuq ylnepo ylno eht m’I“
”.uoy fo erac doog ekat ll’yehT
.llah niam eht fo dne raf eht ta egats eht no doots ailuJ dna lledneW
”’nilrad gniht eruS“
.lledneW detpecretni dna htrof nar eW
”.retaw emos uoy teg s'tel ,emoC“
,dehsiw os eh fi sdnah eerf owt eht fo eno dereffo gnieb lledneW htiw ,s’hctarcS fo eno dna sdnah ym fo eno koot selrahC
.ti htiw gnitoof sih gnidnif llits saw eh fi
.llits doots I tub ,mih dewollof selrahC dna lledneW
.ynoclab eht otni tsrif-enips mih gnidnes
.yawa deklaw dna denrut wodahs eht ,ti was I tnemom ehT
.ycnatiseh ekatrevo ot nageb lasuorA
”!evom gnikcuf s’tel ,retaw naht rekciht s’doolB“ .detuohs selrahC ”!uoy ot enod ev’yeht tahw nees ev’uoY“
.retal sraey eerht ,5791 ,enuJ fo ht8 - ”.enif
.elzzum eht no lledneW dessik dna drawrof denael hctarcS
.lledneW si sihT“
deppart reh dnif ot ylno
.hguorht si thgin eht erofeb ecnaraeppa cilbup a ekam ot evah ot gniog er’eW
.dias lledneW ”.ereh ni lavitsef a ekil s’tI“
,oot selrahC dna uoy evol ot detnaw I fI“
.mih derussa selrahC
.deksa selrahC ”?yako uoY“
.deunitnoc lledneW
,ssik a dna ecarbme na degnahcxe ew ,em dehcaorppa tar ehT
”,rebmemer I seY“
.tsev ym rednu pu wap eno dils eH .dennirg lledneW
.mra reppu ym gnikop ,dias yrraL
”.tihs nelots eht lla tuoba gniksa naht gnidliub eht morf detceje eb ot yaw retsaf neve na dnuof ew sseuG“
,gnol a rof sruo fo yna fo nrecnoc a eb ton lliw eh taht ees ot hguone od lliw dedivorp uoy shpargotohp ehT
.su dniheb ti desolc dna ni reh dewollof I
.wonk t’nod I“ .dehgis I
”.regnol hcum rof toN“
.krow ruoy htiw railimaf rehtar
.dias ailuJ ”,llew yreV“ .dias eh
…lla su revo doots
.mih ecarbme naht erom od ot sselhtaerb oot saw I taht saw tnemtnioppasid ylno eht ,mih dehcaer dah I ecnO
.ronam eht fo sdnuorg eht gnidnuorrus llaw eht ot revo ,srac neewteb kcuns I
em llet ot evah lliw uoY“
.”.tsal ta em m’I ekil leef I
”?uoy t’ndid ,mih htiw llew yrev no tog uoY“ .dias ailuJ
.”!lausnesnoC eb dluohs sniahC ehT“ dna
s’erehT .lortnoc ni dna ,yppans ,tsaf deklat ,ecarg htiw devom eH
.dennirg yrraL ”?ew nac ,won taht evah t’nac eW“
.tfeht eht rof sessylU tserra dluow IBF eht nehT
”.tol a hguorht neeb s’lledneW
.deksa lledneW ”?ecalp eritne siht rof gnibmulp eht did uoy dnA“
.spuc fo noitcelloc a dna retaw fo guj egral a dah pot retnuoc ehT
,lufraF lacsaP yb
”,lortnoc rednu taht evah I“
lleW“ .mih dednimer I
”.gnihtemos gnidih er’uoY“   2 fo 2 traP
.deliaf dna yawa kool ot deirt ,dehsulb xof elbram ehT
.selrahC ot dekool I sa edistuo nageb gniugrA
.tixe eht ta srood elbuod eht sdrawot elbmarcs ew sa deksa lledneW ”?ailuJ s’erehW“
.enummoc eht otni yrraL dewollof I
.munimula dna doow fo edam sgnidliub detfarc-dnah fo spot eht ees dluoc uoy ,llaw eht evobA
”?em tel uoy dluow ,rehto hcae evol eerht uoy dna
,em nees evah ot dah eH
.deksa selrahC ”?raeh uoy did tahW“
”.tuls uoy sllac eh semitemoS“
.erats duorp a htiw em gnixif seye kcalb yssolg htiw ,xof elbram llat a si
”.elbissop sa noos sa secnatsmucric etamitni erom rednu reh yojne ot hsiw
,retteb sevresed rethguad yM“
.tew leef seye ym dna setapissid tug ym ni thgiew dnuop ytfif ehT
.derepsihw dna esolc tnel xof yM
.mih fo sretem 03 nihtiw lohocla fo ffihw tsetniaf eht neve ton
flesreh gnidroffa
.degnahcxe gnieb gnihtemos draeh I ”.esruoc fO“
ym dekcil neht ,spil ym morf desae eH
.nalp eht fo trap lla s’tahT“ .ylmrif dias ailuJ ”,wonk I“ ”.retteb eht
”?ko ,eceip muesum a ton m’I taht ydobyreve dnimer tsuj ,thgirlA
”.etilop dna luftcepser ,dnik tub gnihton neeb s’eh ,raf os tuB
.serusaem egral yllauqe ni
.deunitnoc nam eht ”,tnellecxE“
.tuo reh dewollof dna thgiarts tius sih dellup lledneW .rood eht fo tuo deppets dna edacaf eht otni kcab yletalucammi dils ailuJ ”!gnimoC“ ”!ailuJ“
,esaelp woN“ .eson
.ediw tnew seye s’lledneW
hguone etanutrof era su fo wef oot dna
”.denilced yletilop yrev I tub sey
”.lledneW uoy teem ot desaelp ...lleW“
.detnurg lledneW ”,oN“
…os erew uoy aedi on dah tsuj I
”,ereht tuo sdnah fo riap refas a ton
.hctorc sih no dnah ym gnittup ,dias I
”.uoy knahT“ .deddon lledneW
.tnelis erew stnapucco ruof sti dna moor ehT
.rits sniol ym tlef I .meht evom ot troffe on edam I .shgiht ym no swap sih decalp eH
?kereD tem ew taht rebmemer uoY“
”.egacbir sih otni toof ruoy denilced yletilop yreV“
.ti ynapmocca ot em edisni werg ycnatiseh A
.taht od ot raeb t’ndluoc I dnA
.taht yrt ot gniog saw eh eveileb t’ndluoc I .dehcrul tug yM
,detsetorp eh ”?ylimaf ym tuoba tahW“
.deerga selrahC ,yltnatculeR
.ssertsim gnicnartne na si ,ecnad ekil ,gninnuR .egarim a tsuj saw ti fi derednow I
”.knird naht erom seod eH“
.dias I ”.elim erauqs eht nihtiw nosrep elbapac tsom eht yldetbuodnu s’ehS“
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb seigolohtna owt ni derutaef neeb sah ohw
”.thginot gnola gnimoc rof niaga ecno uoy knaht ot ekil d’I“ -- .selrahC
.mih gnidloh tpek ailuJ
,egacbir ’sessylU ni flesti yrub toof ’selrahC ees ot emit ni tsuj denrut I
,sulP .ytpme flaH“ ”!lluf flah s’tI“
,guj eht morf retaw fo sessalg owt deruop dna deddon I
”yes’truoc ym decitcarp I gniht doog nmaD“
.”?em rof esu nam ruoy seod seman rehto tahW
”.selrahC ksa ot evah d’I“
”.ti raeh ot dalg m’I“
gnimlehwrevo ssenreeuq trevo s’enummoc eht dnif dluow lledneW fi saw em deirrow taht gniht ylno ehT
”.uoy fo erutcip a s’tI“
.dnah s’tar eht nopu wap a gnicalp ,elims a htiw dias lledneW ”.evisserpmi yrev llits s’tI“
.ti dedeen yeht sa gnol sa rof
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“yojne esaelP
,yhtlaeh erehwemos mih teg nac ew renoos ehT“ .denialpxe I
.ynoclab eht no pu morf selrahC ot yas sessylU draeh I
”.su pots ron ,su egduj roN .su ees ot ereh tuo ydobon
.deraeppa I dna selrahC nehw gniugra deppots snotruB ehT
,no emoc hO“ .erom dna erom dennirg tsuj eh dna ylper ot elbanu gnieb peek I
denigami ohw esoht htiw tub
?rehtaf ym fo dnA“
”.ti tbuod I ?revo snwot eerht enummoc tsinummoc a tuB
.ecaf sih revo dehsalf gnihtemos fo rekcilf A
.ecnatsid tsedom a morf eye lufhctaw gnipeek selrahC htiw
.recnad og-og a morf ti denrael I .hctaw ot enoemos tnaw uoy nehw od uoy dnik ehT .ssik fo dnik yppols ,wols a saw tI
,rac eht ot teg ,oG“
.emos derettulf traeh yM
,ekal eht ssorca taob elttil taht lias d’eh woh
.detnaw lla ew tahw saw ti tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.eson ym kcil ot eugnot sih tuo gnikcilf
.deksa lledneW ”?ti …siht sI“
,staob esoht delias eW ?notpmaH pmaC ta
.yawyna emit eht ta toN
”.semoctuo tcefrep rof dnuora pohs ot emit eht evah yltcaxe t’ndid uoy taht etaicerppa osla I tuB“
.delims lledneW .tsal ta dias I
”.uoy remrahc uoy ,skcuhs hO“
.eucebrab laoc degralne na ekil demees tahw ot ffo gnitraped erofeb ,dias yrraL
”.ti od ot woh tsuj wonk I dnA
.demaercs eH ”?em rof ereht tuo ecalp retteb a s’ereht eveileb yllaer uoY
.tniop doog a ekam uoY“ .elims I
.htaerb peed a neht
lledneW“ .seye ym desolc I
.seye ym otni ylpeed dezag lledneW
”neslO lledneW gnivaS :ni yalbmerT rotciV“
.dias eH ”.deneppah lla ti taht yrraL dna ailuJ dna selrahC dna uoy ot sknaht s’tI“
?uoy rof kaeps syawla eh seoD“
.em tsap gnikool dna gninrut erofeb
.ecalp eht morf detaname cisum dna gnirelloh lufreehc fo sdnuos eht ,eucebrab fo llems ehT
…t’nsaw tI .dehcnilf I
.edisni su fo ruof eht derutseg hctarcS
tar a fo erugif ywodahs eht
”.secnaraeppa pu peek tsuJ
.dias eH ”.dalg m’I“
.yltnatcepxe tub ,ylevissergga ton ,em ta derats ehS
.raeh t’ndluoc eh ekil demees ti tub ,yawa teef wef a deppots dah lledneW
.epacse ruo gnikam su fo eerht eht dnim ot mees t’ndid dna
.dias I ”,hctarcS ,lledneW
ot-dnabsuh eht
…t’ndid I“ .deplug I
”.ti ni erusserp erom s’ereht esuac‘ seog retaw eht retsaf eht ,epip eht rellams eht tuo serugif eh neht os...“
,ti gnikahs dna wap eht gnikat ,deilper xof elbram eht
.dias yrraL ”.nrecnoc ruoy etaicerppa I“
”?uoy htiw strilf yug toh a emit yreve siht od uoy od
”?meht teg uoy diD“
yruxul eht evah ot
,emoctuo elbatpecca na eb ot demees lledneW gnikat sU
.reh ta pu gnirats ,ti nopu tas
;su fo htob fo stseretni tseb eht rof dna
.tar rednels a ekil tol a dekool taht wodahs A
saw tahT .ytnuob a rof meht egnahcxe ot dennalP
.delkcuhc yrraL ”.rehtegot deldnub sgiwt elpuoc a erew uoy ,uoy tem tsrif I nehw tub haeY“
.noitatiseh tuohtiw dias I ”.seY“
.sthguoht dnoces evah ot nageb I
”?ti dessim I dna deirram tog tsuj uoy fo eerht eht
.dekrims yrraL ”?suoegrog he ,kcart gninnur eht morf yawa yaw elttiL“
.ruof ot noisnapxe s’ylimaf eht emoclew dluow yrehcuabed fo ecarbme ehT
.mih yletinifed saw ti ,ezah eht hguorht tuB
,tar ypparcs a saw etag eht ta dootS
,lliw-lli tuohtiw ,lledneW“
,delaever yllanif si noitatneiro elbitapmocni na nehw dedne spihsnoitaleR
,suht dnA .hcnup driht a werht esle enoemos ,moor eht fo renroc raf eht nI
.deraeppa ti tnemom eht reviaw ot nageb elims ehT
.rae ym ot tuons sih desserp eH
”.muesum on t’nia ydob yM“
.selrahC dluoc rehtieN
.tius dewollof ew dna rac eht fo tuo debmilc eH
,em dniheb erew ynoclab eht ot pu spets ehT
.detnap I ”.tnemngissa hguoT“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.dias eH ”.yalbmerT rM
gnitseggus tsuj m’I“
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“
os ecalp siht si woH“
,noitcartsid a etaerc ylbacilpxeni ot elba saw ailuJ
.flesym dna selrahC neewteb spets eht gnikcolb dna gnivom ,dias xof dlo ehT ”?ycavirp fo parcs a neve htiw uoy taert ton eh seoD
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.eil slliks ruoy reverehw
.dias lledneW ”?ti t’nsah ,ylrae devirra sah renniD“
,tnemom eht evah meht tel eW
fo trap lanif dna
.wap s’lledneW gnikat ,dias tar ehT
.ecalp reeuq ,efas a ot mih thguorb uoY“ .dias yrraL
.deggur dna tfos won ,elbatrofmocnu dna ffits ecno
.tekcaj ym fo tuo enizagam eht dellup I
.ecalp reeuq yrev a s’tI“ .lledneW ot denialpxe selrahC
.sredluohs ym dnuof ,tsehc ym htiw dehsinif gnivah ,swap siH
.ylsselhtaerb detcejbo I ”.etuc ton m’I“  .dias eH
.wap sih ni dnah ym sekat eH
”.dne eht ni detnaw yeht tahw tog ydobyreve taht smees tI“
.dnuorg eht ot taots eht gnilkcat lledneW thguac I ,eye ym fo renroc eht fo tuO
.strohs ym otno yaw rieht devom swap siH
taht erawanu yltnetnoc ,nem ruoF
”.morf emac eseht erehw s’taht oS“
.wap s’lledneW otni ti gnihsup dna ssalg a pu gnikcip
”.hguoht ot uoy detnaw eH“
,elbissopmi dnif ylneddus yeht
.mih erolpxe ot detrats swap nwo yM
.gnileer xof dlo eht dnes dna lluks htiw tsif tcennoc ot retsaf neeb dah xof ym tub
,dias I ”,esruoc fO“
.nac I tahw od ll’I“
.mih ekil nam a gnittifeB
.deksa yrraL ”?elbatrofmocnU“
,bulcthgin a saw esle erehwyreve dna
.mih sdrawot deretnuas hctarcS ”.lledneW olleh yhW“
.htgnerts dnuof-wen sih tibihni yromem rieht tel ot desufer lledneW tub
.ronam eht morf stcafitra nelots wef a gniveirter saw ehS
,tnemom a roF .noziroh eht ot mlap a desiar I erofeb ,sselhtaerb ,desuap I
.tsal ta dias ehS
”.noitnetta hguone gniyap neeb t’nevah yllaer I sseug I
”?ereht tcepxe I dluohs sgniht adnik …tahW“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
ffo tuc strohs mined fo riap a dna stoob etterehtael ydruts ni
.t’nevah ew on ,on …I hO“
.ni depparts dna tuhs rood eht gnulf I
.knurd mih gnidnif
.fo tnorf eht nwod deffuts wap a dah yrraL taht snaej fo tes A
.ecaps eht dellif eh dna emit ni kaeps t’ndid I .enog gnol
.em gnissik neht ,gnicarbme ,deksa eH ”?yako uoY“
.dennirg selrahC ”?lledneW s’woH“
”neslO lledneW gnivaS
”.taht rewsna ot evah t’nod uoY“ selrahC dnimer dna nrut I
”?taht ot pu uoy erA
.kcen ym no htaerb toh sih ,depsag lledneW ”?tsom uoy sllac eh
.tar eht gnissik dna gnicarbme dna drawrof gniggoj ,dellac selrahC ”!hctarcS“
.gnoht dedduts kcalb a dna stoob etterehtael hgih-eenk
.eceip eno ni gnineve siht hguorht teg ot evah ew ,tsriF“
.moor eht fo weiv retteb a teg ot osla tub ,ecaps meht evig ot htob ,tib a kcab gnuh I
.egap yrruFoS sih no
”.retaw eht ni enon erew ereht taht uoy dlot yeht litnu hsif wef a hctac ot deirt neve uoy
”.niaga ksam a raew ot evah t’now uoy ,enod s’thginot ecnO
”?liatne ’ecnaraeppa cilbup‘ siht seod tahW“
.htrof emac tnemevom on ,sdrow eht fo thgiew eht morf esluvnoc dluohs moor eht erehW
”,yojne ot sruoy eb llahs hcihw
”.eman retteb hcum a s’tahT“
I yas erad I hguohT“ .dias ailuJ ”.seY“
.dennirg tnedor eht ”,won yhs eb t’nod lleW“
.refas erehwyna fo kniht t’ndluoc I ,emit eht tA
.niaga yawa dekool I ”.derettalf m’I“
.evitamrofsnart dna gnimoclew os neeb sah ecalp elohw sihT“
”.ti ekam ot gniog s’eh kniht I“
euqisyhp denot ,rednels a lledneW nevig dah enummoc eht no krow fo sruoh gnoL
”,ecalp siht ni dna ylimaf ruoy htiw efas eb ot gniog t’nsi lledneW“
,shgiht ym ta ,dedda eH ”,eseht dnA“
,dias eH ”.rethguad ym yrram ot thgir ruoy tuoba yletavirp klat ll’ew ,enod s’taht ecno dnA .dooG“
”.od lliw tseipmiks eht ylnO“
dluoW“ .dah netfo eh ssenizzuf ,mraw taht htiw dias yrraL
.sdnah fo riap efas ,doog a si yrraL ,dias gnieb tahT
”.efil ym lla ti gniod neeb ev’I“
.elihw a rof tpew eh erehw
.enim ot yltneg spil sih gnisserp erofeb ,dias yrraL
.enot retfos a ni emit siht ,dias eH
.selrahC dna flesym ot kcab dekool ehS .dias eh
.epacse na rotciV dna
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.elkcuhc a htiw derepsihw selrahC ”..elbatrofmoc gnitteg s’eh woN“
.em dniheb spetstoof draeh I ,did ew sA
.noitucexe ruoy dna noitamrofni ruoy ,nalp ruoy saw tI“
”neslO lledneW gnivaS
.egats eht evael ot detrats neht
”.retal uoy llet ll’I“ ”…ailuJ sI“
dessik eW .t’ndid I oS
.sdnah sih morf rewop fo niarg tsal eht gnilaets naem dluow taht tuB
”.sseug I ,haeY“ .dehgis I
,redluohs reh tsniaga daeh s’lledneW dediug ailuJ
.enola saw lledneW taht deciton dah yart sknird eht htiw taots eht ,yawa teef erom wef A
.tnorf lohocla eht no esrow neve neeb evah dluow hcihw
”.ytinummoc ruoy fo trap lufrednow a semoceb eh epoh I“ .deddon I
.deksa sessylU ”?dnuob uoy era mohw ot nehT ?hO“
.ti revocsid ot emit tseb eht t’nsaw siht tuB
.deppots llaftoof s’lledneW
.s’tar eht ot spil sih desserp dna drawrof desae neht ,telracs dehsulb xof ehT
.noissimo hguorht hctorc ym gnisaeT
”.mra reh no xof der rehtona htiw retteb hcum kool dluow ehS
.deerga selrahC ”,esruoc fO“
.enog tsomla erew shgiht dna stsirw no sracs ehT
”.smelborp esoht fo tsom sexif esicrexE
”,yrraL ,tekcap laerec a morf uoy wonk t’nseod
.mih ot txen tas I dna sloots eht fo eno no tas eH
.enizagam eht fo egap taht no saw ohw derebmemer I ,ylnedduS
,dias taots eht ”,pis eno tsuj …no emoc hO“ ”.knurd a ton m’I“
-  ”.wonk ew hO“ .ssa ym dezeeuqs dna dehgual yrraL
.spih sih ot nwod devom sdnah yM
.tsal ta em deksa xof ym ”?ronam eht ta tol gnikrap eht ni ees uoy did tahW“ ”.si eh kniht I“
.sgel sih daerps mih eciton t’ndid tsomla I dna em ecaf ot erugif sih denrut eH
ma I ssefnoc tsum I“ .ylsuovren delims xof ehT
.detsisni I ”!no emoc ,ecalp eht tsuj wonk eW“
.detsetorp I ”,segdurg dloh mih ekil srekcufrehtom hcir tub ,seod eH“
.moor eht ot rood eht ta gnippots ,ailuJ ot dias I
,emit tsaL   .ksam eht
.ti rof revoc yltnatsni tsomla mih was neht ,gnihtemos deciton eh sa nediw ezag s’yrraL dehctaw I
.ylluftsiw dias selrahC ”.si eruS“
.niaga delims dna deddon eh dna denruter erusopmoc sih neht tub ,dnoces a tsuj rof yrraL tih noitazilaeR ”.lacol
,edirP yppaH .stsacdop ruoy
.gnola lla wenk ehs taht niatrec tsomla m’I
.tnedor a gnilbmeser etteuohlis A
”.t’nia eh dna ,ailuJ yrram ot lledneW tnaw t’ndid eH“
.delworg xof ym ”!elas rof ton m’I“
dna s’lledneW ot spil ym gnisserp yllanif erofeb ,dias I
.saw lledneW siht
”,sserdda nA“ .detseuqer I
”.dednetni ehs eno eht ton fi neve
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.ecalp siht fo trofmoc rehtona saw noitatiseh tsethgils eht neve tuohtiw nam rehtona htiw dnah-ni-dnah gniklaW
”.elttob retaw taht pu llif tsael tA“
.snaej sih ni sseltrihs ,gnihctaw doots selrahC gniees
eman eht wonk uoy od tuB“
.rood eht fo tnorf ni doots I .ksed eht ot txen riahc eht no tas selrahC
lledneW .deb eht ediseb doots ailuJ
”!edisni niS !ylno stludA“ ,”!snaeM eht ezieS“
.erom hsulb mih ekam ot demees ylno os gniod hguoht
”?gnidih I ma tahW“
.elbissop si reh rof efil retteb a taht
.deilper eh ”!eilrahC ydwoH“
”.flesruoy rof eeS“
.mih yortsed oT .mih esucca oT .mih tpurretni ot reh gniggeb tsomlA
.detsetorp I ”.sruoy naht rellams thgis nmad
.gnibbos s’lledneW saw dnuos ylno ehT
.skcits eht ni tuo yaw ,erehwon fo elddim eht ni saw enummoc ehT
.daeh ym htiw gnikcuf yllaeR“
.tsiser nac I evol esohw nam a t’nsi yrraL
.smra s’nam a ni sdne ti nehw elbarusaelp yrev si nur A
”.ylevol eb dluow tahT“
.s’hctarcS gnikat dna
”.emit rennid ylraen s’tI ?sretrauq gninid eht ot hguorht stseug ruo ekat ot elba eb uoy dluoW“ .dias yrraL ”,hctarcS“
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.gnisserp erom eb ot gniog saw ytefas s’lledneW tub ,rehtegot nioj ot desoppus erew stod eseht fo lla woh tuoba rehtruf eborp ot tuoba saw I
.dias lledneW ”,notruB rM ,seY“
,em erofeb dootS .yltaerg degnahc sah erugif eht tuB .railimaf si eciov ehT ”,llew lleW“
.flesreh esopmoc ot tnemom a koot ailuJ
a tnes taht yaw a ni ti gninnacs ,erugif ym ot kcab devom ezag dexaler siH
,dennirg eh ”!od nac nosrep a gniht etilop tsom eht s’tI“
.sessylU rehtaf eliv dna hcir reh yb
”.rouqil erom mih lles ot neek t’nera taht semoctuo ton ylniatreC“
.nekorb eb tsum taht sesimorp
revir eht ot nwod tnew ew nehw rebmemer uoy oD“
,won rethguad ym tem ev’uoy ,em lleT“
evisserpxe ylesobrev ,yldnuoforp woh dna dah dlo fo lledneW eht noisserpxe elttil woh ebircsed ot drah s’tI
demees tI .rehto hcae gnoma thgif ot neek demees hcir eht tub ,sredistuo sa dekcatta teg ot su fo eerht eht detcepxe I
”?dnuora yrraL sI“ .deilper hctarcS
”.efas er’uoy ees ot dalg m’I .lledneW“
.eno doog a dnuof yllanif d’yeht dna ,esucxe na detnaw enoyreve ekil
.wap egral a tuo gnidloh ,dias yrraL ”,erofeb tem ev’ew kniht t’nod I“
”,revo si pihsnoitaler siht
...“ – .ti gnikat ,deilper I ”.oot uoy evol I“
ll’eH !ti evaeL“ .erom yna gniod morf mih gnippots dna htrof gninnur ,detuohs I ”!selrahC“
esnes a ni erew yeht rof
.teef sih ta won ,detaeper lledneW ”,secnaraeppa pu gnipeeK“
”.tae ot gnihtemos uoy teg s’tel ,no emoC“
.detsisni eh ”,teprac der eht dial tsuj I
.selrahC ot deppiuq I
”?tuoba klat ot ekil uoy dluow tahW“
.xof elbram eht ot denruter ezag yM
.rood eht ta gnignab a saw ereht ylnedduS
.deddon dna htaerb a koot ehs ,htuom sih desolc lledneW nehW
.niaga delims yrraL .deddon I
.yllacitsacras nageb lledneW ”,on hO“ .deksa yrraL
.dias nam naeporuE eht
”?dneirf…sih dna mih fo sgnitniap eht su dewohs eH
.nam eht ta kool a tog I ,did I sA
.ot tpmetta on edam ailuJ
s’erehT .yalbmerT rM tsurt I .on ,oN“ ”?efas mih peek ot ytiliba rieht tbuod ew fi meht morf mih eveirter nac I .thgir s’tahT“
,yhW .srats eht rednu dnuora delias eW“ .dias ehs
.moor sih ni siht dah eH“
”?emit erom eno s’tahW .thginot ecno flesruoy fo loof a edam ydaerla ev’uoY“
”?od ew llahs revetahw ,ezag elam ehT“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.mih rof sdrow eht yas t’ndluoc ehs taht dnatsrednu ot demees tsuj ehS
.tuo pleh dna krow ot uoy tcepxe ot gniog era yeht
,emoh ta mih troppus ot tegdub doof ro moor evah t’ndid eW
.elttil yrev dias tub
,meht htiw ton seil tluaf eht dnA
,ailuJ teg ot tfel dah rotciV
.dias ailuJ ”?yenom eht tuoba erac t’nod
no gnidnaL .neve ailuJ tsaP
.eb-ot-dnabsuh reh ediseb nwod tas dna htrof deppets ehS
.derettahs eh ,taht htiW
.ydob enorp sih nopu nwod stirips dna ssalg gniniar dna nwod nam eht gninnip
a er’yehT“ .tsehc ym ta kool ot tsev ym detfil neht dna ”...eseht dna hO“
,tpek neeb evah reven dluoc sesimorp esoht
”.rotciV em llaC“ .delims I ”,esaelP“
.truoC eht ni etoyoC ruoy ,ozirraC yb uoy rof daer
”.sliatne taht sgniht doog eht lla ot pu gnitteg si dna ahtnamaS deman namow a gniees s’ehs draeh I tsaL“ ”?llew ehs sI
.slarum ni derevoc llaw leets-teehs dna doow llams a yb dednuorrus saw tI
.enummoc eht fo egde eht no doots wodahs a deciton I eye ym fo renroc eht fo tuo ,did I sa tub ,sresuort sih elkcubnu ot em degaruocne selrahC ”.od I kniht I“
”ta gnikool htrow gnihtemos ti evig ot evah ll’eW“
”.rennid rof su nioj
.ksam ytpme ,yppah a no gnittup saw ti ,ta ecitcarp dah ylekil d'eh gniht eno saw ereht fi ;ylniatrec rekaeps tnetepmoc a saw eh tuB
.rac eht sdrawot su del selrahC dna deerga eH
.epacse s’lledneW dna reh dnuf ot gniog saw ehs woh
taht rebmemer tsum ew yletamitlu tuB
”?od nac nam a etilop erom gnihtyna wonk uoy oD“
”-hw em lleT“ .nageb I ”,nalp sihT“
.selrahC ,deruc eb nac toggaf a gnieB“ yas sessylU draeh I ,em dniheb morf dnA
,htgnel taerg ta ekops lledneW
”.eripme etatse laer ’sessylU fo gnilppot eht morf tol a niag ot dnats I ,sediseB
”.rotciV ,stsirw sih was I“ .dehgis yrraL
”!won ,og ot tog ev’eW“
.edisni ailuJ gnirutseg dna rood eht gninepo ,dias I ”,gnihtemos tuB
.lledneW ot ylmrif
”.pal ruoy ni thgir mottob kcor ta s’ohw rerimda terces a gnippord erofeb tsrif uoy deksa evah dluohs I“
.dedaeh saw siht erehw wenk I
.ti dnuora sloots htiw sretnuoc eht fo eno ot revo em del eH
,no gniog toL“
ytterp dna emosdnah saw eH
.em derussa selrahC
,ni nrow ylivaeh neeb dah
”,haeY ?tahw wonk uoY“
.sknird erom ni derevoc elbat a otni roolf eht ssorca mih deppihw neht ,htgnel smra ot tuo taots eht gnuws dah lledneW
.enileye s’hctarcS ta ezag sih gnipeek saw elggurts ylno s’xof eht demees ti tuB .llew siht gnikat saw eh fi ees ot lledneW ta decnalg I .lward deyenoh
,selrahC ta gnuws ,teef sih ot tog dah sessylU ,em dniheb morF
erow eh strohs ypmiks esoht fo mined ehT
”.thgin lla dna yad lla uoy htiw gnitrilf nem etanoitceffa yrev evah ot tcepxe ,revewoH
.deksa lledneW ”?won tahW“
.ereht saw eh gniwonk em yb devres retteb saw lliw lli sih ro ,lliw lli on dah eh rehtiE
.ailuJ ot ytilauxes sih ssefnoc dluohs eh taht mih decnivnoc selrahC .tekcop sih ni
?oot uoy rof efil retteb a …spahrep dnA
.deksa taots eht ”?lledneW ,knird rehtona rof eraC“
nosrep laer a yb ton edam
.trap tnatropmi eht saw lledneW dna flesruoy fo ytefas ehT“
”.ti deen t’nseod ehs erus nmad m’I
.tol gnikrap eht fo tuo evird ot nageb selrahC
.ot desu gnitteg emos koot yllanoisacco taht gnihtemos llits ,gniticxe saw tI
su dlot eH .taob eht su tnel ohw eno eht saw eH
.em dnuora gnitturts ,dias eH
…si edoc sserd ehT“
”…dna …selrahC !rotciV“ .delims I ”,yrraL“
,uoy emalb t’nod I“ .redluohs ym no mra sih tup eilloc redrob ehT
”?yalbmerT rM ,’dneirf‘ ruoy ti sI“
.noitseuq tnellecxe na tahW
”.strohs eseht ni ssa ruoy ees annaw ohw syug fo not a s’ereht
.deilper xof ym ”,yaw a sah evoL“
.su erofeb deraeppa taoctsiaw dna spahc rehtael ni eilloc redrob tuots eht nehw ti yreuq ot tuoba saw I
.noitnetta ro esualppa naht os erom kcabdeef enohporcim yb yltsom deinapmocca ,emeht lartnec siht dnuora ylegral devlover dias saw tahW
.deirruh I ,em ta gnikool saw eh dezilaer I nehW
,gnoL .enog si xof deifirret ,suoixna tahT
.dias I ”,yrgnuh ton m’I“
,yrraL evol I sa tsuj
”.rotciV esruoc fo yhW“
,semit fo tseb eht ta ,ssecorp yssem a eb nac tuo gnimoC
”.llew yap nac I ,gnipleh eunitnoc ot gnilliw era owt uoy fI“
,esualppa decrof ylthgils ,thgil ot ,sserdda sih dehsinif lledneW
”?tulS naht retteb eb dluoc tahW“
.tsal ta mih ta pu dekool I
dnoces a rof desolc seyE
t’niA“ .deksa xof elbram ehT
”?ot meht gnikat uoy era erehW“
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.yltnedifnoc dias nam eht ”,selrahC“
.dias eH ”.emas eht tuobA“ ”?uoY .yb teg ll’I tub
.t’ndid ehs taht eveileb t’ndluoc I .wenk ehS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.tol gnikrap eht dehcaorppa dna gnidliub eht fo renroc eht dednuor eW
eno siht piks esaelp
,htmraw dna retlehs ,doof rof nruter ni ,lleW“
,noitalpmetnoc ni
.llew uoy od ll’taht ecalp a wonk eW“
,dias eH ”?dnatsrednu ew od ,enecs rehtona evah ton lliw eW“
.dias I ”,wonk dluohs uoy gniht erom enO“
”?siht no ecnatsissa reh deyojne ev’uoy tsurt I“
”.tol a ekil dnuos flah t’nod ti ,taht ekil ti drow uoy nehw ,lleW“
”,hauqassI ni tuo sruo fo dneirf esolc yrev a yb nur enummoc a ot uoy gnikat er’eW“
”.eladreduaL yrraL ,yrraL s’eman yM“
”,krow ot gniog reven si egairram tahT“
.em htiw seson gnibbur ,deilper I ”.yako m’I“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.ssa ym gnittap ,dias eH ”.sruoy fo strohs ynit eseht s’ti teb I“
.ti hctac t’ndid I tub
,tekcaj mined ffo-tuc a ni desserd
.delkcuhc eh ”,stnap emos gniraew eb neve thgim eh draeh I tsal ,si erus eH“ .hctarcS deksa I
.ylluftsiw tsomla ,dias selrahC ”.si erus tI“
.meht elots eh taht erawa edam neeb evah IBF ehT“
.llaw eht revo enoemos ot gniklat reh draeh I“ .dias I ”.ailuJ“
”.strohs ruoy sekam ohw
”?eh t’nsaW .nam ylevol a hcus saw eH“
,ti otni demmals taots eht nehw despalloc tI
.dias ailuJ ”?ksaM rebaK eht dna dnomaiD arogA
”.su fo lla retfa og ylekil lliw eH
.deunitnoc xof dlo eht ”,retteb hcum
,revo dekool ylprahs I ”-ga eh nehW“
”.oot eM .hguone eurT“ .delkcac lledneW
,wap a gnihctertstuo ,yllamrof yrev ,deilper xof elbram eht ”,olleH“
.elttil a derettulf traeh yM .enim naht retsaf detrad seye siH
”?dniheb ailuJ evael ot gniog ew erA“
.deddon eH .mih deksa ehS
.yaw yna ni tcaer t’ndid eh tub
?evah ew did eciohc tahw tuB
.delrans selrahC ”?era uoy kniht I tahw gnitseggus uoy erA“
,gnihtemos elbmum lledneW draeh I
.daeh sih revo gniylf elttob a gnikcud
”?uoy od ,thgirfegats evah t’nod owt eht ,nam wA“
.dennirg eilloc redrob ehT ”.sruoh rof dnuora gninnur neeb ev’uoY !tihslluB“
.derepsihw I ”,setunim wef a eb ll’I
,ytnuob rieht gnimialc dna IBF eht ot meht gnikat eb lliw ahtnamaS“ .deksa ailuJ
.gnisserac ni yoj taerg dnuof sdnah ym taht
.kcab reh dniheb smrA
.kcab doots I dna selrahC
”.dnab eht morf gnos a yb dewolloF“ .dias ailuJ
,eb dluoc strohs sa trohs sa tuoba
.mih derussa ailuJ
sa sgniht hcus desuopse hcihw slaruM
.taht rof kool ot kniht
.eciov s’yrraL yb detpurretni saw nur yM ”!rotciV“
.dluow I efil sih evas oT .I dluoc rehtieN
”,od I esruoc fO“ ”?rebmemer uoy od
”…tuo pleh ot ekil …I“
.dne on ot laeh mih pleh dluow
”...ailuJ ,yag m’I ,eurt s’tI“
”?ralucitrap ni uoy derih ailuJ yhw tuo krow uoY“
.”uoy ot emas ,uoy knahT“
,gnibmulp dna sepip fo sehcteks emos lledneW gniwohs hctarcS dnif ot llah gninid egral eht otni deklaw eW
.skcabward dah yrraL ot lledneW gnikaT ”.’lanoitpo‘
.desaet eH ”.t’ndluoc uoy kniht ot gninnigeb saw I“
.etiuq ton tub ,gnidnuos hcnerF ylthgilS .naeporuE .eciov elam A
.su tuoba wonk ot elpoep rof ddo
.wap sih gnireffo ,dias eH ”.uoy evol I“
,taes eht tih ssa ym tnemom eht dna rac eht ot denruter I
,neslO lledneW fo yresim tesno eht etagitsevni ot derih saw yalbmerT rotciV
.delbmert spil siH ”…I !ailuJ“
.delims dna elttil a dehsulb eH
dna cidolem ,tfos a ni ,dias eh
”?su retfa emoc dna evil ew erehw tuo dnif ot gniog si sessylU kniht uoy oD“
,emoh ti llac ohw elpoep eht ro stneserper ti tahw ,enummoc siht stcepsersid eh fI
,smaerd eht ,snalp eht gnigdurgeb seilimaf
”.rentrap sih dna yalbmerT htiw s’eH“ ”?efas lledneW sI“
”.eerga I nehW“ ”-seerga eh fi ,tuB“ .yllufhturt dias I
”.llirg eht pu tes og attoG“
.rac eht sdrawot ssorca kcab tperc I ,evom ot tuoba erew yeht taht gnizilaeR
.ti koot tar eht fi ees ot ylesolc oot gnikool ton tub
”.rotciV ,efil sih gnivas ysub elttil a erew uoY“
.ylsseltroffe deilper ehs ”,uoy era oS“
.spets eht fo pot eht ta doots saw selrahC dna
.su demrofni sessylU ”.setunim evif ni si tsaot ehT“
.seye ym epiw dna hgis I
.ti hguorht dekcilf dna enizagam eht koot yrraL
?os taht sI“ .pil ym tib I
enizagam a morf egap a gnidih saw lledneW taht dnuof rotciV ,siht fo esruoc eht hguorhT
”.tekcop sih ni pu dedlof dna ti fo tuo nrot egap a s’erehT
,enummoc sih ta knird eb dluow erehT
.reppiz s’elrahC nwod llup yrraL draeh I
.redduhs dna elbmert ot detrats lledneW
.deneppah gnihton ,elihw a roF
?epacsdnal eht tniap dna edis raf eht no pu krap neht
.sdrawno lledneW del dna deddon selrahC
.lledneW dedulcni ”lla ew“ ,ereh morf dnA
,pleh rof ksa t’ndid ehs fI“
!emoh ym si sihT“ .delworg lledneW ”?erehW“ .detuohs I ”!evom ot tog ev’ew ,no emoC“
”.ylimaf ym pleh ot dluoc I tahw gniod tsuj saw I tuB“ .dehsulb tar ehT
.ereh dnuora motsuc eht saw sa
”?nwod tis ot ekil uoy
-- ”.efas s’ailuJ tuB“ .dias I ”,retal uoy llet ll’I“
”…yad lla ronam siht ni neeb ev’uoy
.tem ezag s’yrraL dna lledneW .nageb yrraL
.dias eH ”.uoy llac dnabsuh ym raeh I eman ylno eht ton s’ti tuB“