.seye sih otni derats I
.emoh ti edam yllanif I ,gniklaw fo ruoh na tuoba retfA
”.aciremA ssorca pirt gnol a saw tI
.dat a delbmuf neht ,desuap eH
.ton did yehT .raeppasid
dah I .retiuqes-non A
llems yllanif dluoc I ,lisab dna otamot fo amora mraw eht rednU
”.kcis eb thgim I kniht I“
.elbitsiserri dnuof I hcihw
.tsal ta dias I ”.gnorw
.hsid eht fo lufhtuom rehtona koot I tcejbus eht gnignahC
”.uoy t’nevah ,siht rof enil eht no efil ruoy tup ev’uoY“  ”.seil lla saw tI
.dias I ”.t’nseod tI“
.dekrims I
”~ecnereffid eht sekam syawla edis ym ta uoy gnivah ,uoy knaht yhW“
.kcab mih ssik I dna em sessik eH
.traeh ym no yltcerid selbac repmuj tup d’enoemos
.gnirevihs dna gniyrc em
”.ti eetnaraug nac I .yad eno kcab yot rieht tnaw ll’yehT“ .detnurg I ”.tuo
…tahT .evol saw sihT
.evil ot ecalp a dnif ot gniyrt saw I ,egdab evitceted etavirp ym teg ot gniyrt spooh hguorht gnipmuj t’nsaw I fI
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,em gnidloh mih ,elihw a rof ereht tas eW
.emit eht ta ton ,xes yag dah reven d’I
.flesym ekil nam gniraew-tius gnithgif-emirc
,nam thgiarts a si yalbmerT rotciV fi nevE
a htiw evol ni gnieb ta detautafni
”.ti terger ot niatnuof a ot semoc ehs dnA .esor a htiw dereviled ecnavda citnamor a stcejer ohw lrig siht tuoba s’tI“
,dloc a eb ot gniog
.elbaeerga demees tI
.tneserp eluY sih sa mubla remlaP dna ekaL ,nosremE tsrif eht tog d’I moordeb eht ni neddiH
.ecrof elbappotsnu
.llacer I sa elttil a kael I .rebmemer I
”.od ot tnaw t’nod uoy gnihtyna od ot evah t’nod uoY“
niaga flesym dlot I tuB
eht otni erats ot nrut sih koot eH .detnurg eH ”.tihS“
”.regnis on m’I tub ,seY“
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”thgiN eht esuaceB - ni yalbmerT rotciV“ saw sihT      .evol ekil
tsuj s’ti ,rehtona ro yaw eno em hsuP .em rednih ro pleh t’nseod noitamrofni sihT
.wonk ot t’nerew uoY“ .deddon selrahC
.goD fo ecioV ehT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.gniyas saw eh sdrow eht revo eciov s’selrahC fo dnuos eht yb detcartsid emoceb
,raey a ni ,thginot
.niaga detrulb I ”.xes tuobA“
dna elkcarc ti ot denetsiL
,htnom a ni eb ti rehtehW
.ti mrifnoc ot yrassecen yllaer t’nsaw gnikool ,tcaf nI
.eson ot eson gnidnats ,su neewteb ecnatsid eht gnisolc
sruoh rednet ,mraw dneps dna steknalb hsulp ,tfos nopu yal
em dnuora smra sih depparw
.rehtegot ti eceip t’ndluoc I tub ,ecnetnes taht fo trap dnoces a saw erehT
.ereh yaw eht lla ti ekat ot elba neeb evt’ndluow I ,dluoc ew fi dna
.dessorc saw nocibur ehT .dehcuot I
.eciwt ro ecno flesym enod rO
,deksa I ”?yako kcab klaw ehT“
,semoh til-ylthgirb erew deklaw I steerts eht dnuora llA
.snoegnud xes ni ffuts od ohw elpoep fo dnik eht tem ev’I dnA
”.sracxob ni gnilevart reeuq ekorb a sa raey a tneps I“ .deksa I
detnaw I tahw did dna pu doots yllanif I“
.dias I ”.ti tnaw I“
ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
dah ylno d’I dnA
.fo demaerd reve d’I gnihtyreve saw ti …yldognu ,enecsbo
.hcuoc eht ot moor eht ssorca em koot neht ,guh a otni em desae eH
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.eltbus ton s’tI .sgel ym neewteb nwod dekool I  .retal ton
.snosaer thgir eht rof nar uoy
.hcuoc eht no kcab depmuls dna dehgis eH
tsuj saw won rof tub ,yleguh worg dluow hcihw noitcelloc A
.selrahC fo esoht dna ,sniol ym fo gnirrits eht llems dluoc I .hctiwt a evag eson yM
elttil a tuo stel eH
ohw syug emos eb tsuj nac xes yaG“
…si evoL .rehtien t’nera ohw elpoep fo hcnub a
.rac eht ni retteb hcum neeb evah dluow ti tbuoD
”…tub ,ffuts adnik taht od ot tnaw
?sgnivas fo sraey elpuoc
”.evol tuoba si doG“
”?hcuoc siht gnirahs
.siht od em tel t’ndluow
,raewrednu ruo ni ereht tas eW
.niaga em htiw tas neht
teg dna skcart niart eht ot lleh ekil nur ot dah I
.siht od t’ndluoc I
.emertxe taht eb ot deen t’nseod xes tuB“
.lasuora fo taeh eht tsrif tA
.sllarevo ysaerg sih fo tuo gnippils saw xof ym dna
”.uoy rof gnihtemos tog ylno I
”.ytic eht otni yaw eht lla kcoldirg saw tI
demees ylno eH .yenom rof flesmih dlos d’eh tahT
.ereht fo tuo toocs ot ykcul
.kcab ti edam ydaerla dah selrahC os ,no erew sthgil ehT
”.xes yag fo sdnik fo sdaol era erehT“
sresuort yM .erom dna
,tew ylsuoiciv erew s’elttaeS dna
sih fo yldnof ekops I nehw
.hgiht ym ot nwod desae wap siH
,sredluohs sih revo yltpeknu
”.ocixeM we	N ni yug emos rof rood nrab a hcatta-er ot dah I kniht
dna senob ym gnisae erif eht fo taeh eht
.esiwrehto dias dnim ym fo renroc eht ni lived
.evE samtsirhC no eciffo eht morf emoh deklaw I
.tsaef dna reyarp rof gnitagergnoc seilimaf htiw dellif
.noitarepsed fo ,ecnaifed fo tca na sa sresuba ruoy morf yawa gninnuR“
.tsrub dah mad ehT .tuo deruop
”.hguoht tneserp eluY a uoy teg did
mih tel ,nam a htiw xes dah I fi tahT
naht erom ni detseretni saw selrahC taht tpecca ot
”.od I doG emas eht swonk ohw esle enoemos dnif thgim I yad enO“
.niaga seye nrubua mraw sih otni kool
- ni yalbmerT rotciV“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ecap s’lians a ta dessap dah shtnom thgie tsrif esohT
.esrevinu eht fo xulf yrev eht fo tfaw llams a ekiL
.ria mraw fo tsalb htiw deteerg saw I ,esuoh eht deretne I sA
hguoht ,stcepser emos ni riah sih ;ni delknirps setubirtta eninimef deredisnoc-llew
”.daeha thgir oG“ ”?dnim t’nod uoy fi
.od elpoep nees ev’I gnihtemos s’ti
,sepicer erahs …ot klat ot
rof mret lla-hctac a s’ti
redneg sih desserpxe
”.dednuorg leef ot dna efil etarbelec ot
saw ti dlot saw I .xes yag dah reven ev’I“
”thgiN eht esuaceB
.ti tuoba thguoht I erom eht detacilpmoc erom emaceb tub ,ti dias I tnemom eht diputs dednuos taht noitseuq A .ksa I ”?xes siht sI“ .sullahp ot sullahP .tsehc ot tsehC
.em ot resolc stfihs eH
.detnaw uoy tahw ton …s’ti fi neppah thgim tahw tuoba yrrow
elggig syawla dluow selrahC
,naem I .tiag sih ,yltnacifingis tsom
.htmraw sih ni em gnipolevne
.ti ta esrow dna esrow emoceb rehtaf dna rehtom ym was I ,pu werg I sA  .did
reven tsum I em dlot ydob ym ni peed gnihtemoS
,ot tnaw uoy fi muc nac uoY
.resolc gnitoocs erofeb ,esiwekil od xof ym dehctaw I
.redluohs sih ot daeh ym desserp I dna ,smra sih otni em dediug selrahC ”.srieht toN
.niaga flesym ertnec ot deirt I .nwod enog
,nehctik eht otni kcab deppets selrahC  .detnurg I
rehtaf dna rehtom ym tahw ekilnu yrev saw tI .od srevol tahw
,floWcaM boR si sihT
taht tahw fo tpecnoc yna dah em dlo raey neetenin taht toN
.detnaw esle enoyreve tahw toN .egnahc a rof
.dluoc ylbissop teef ym naht retteb od lliw enim fo stoob gib eseht wonk I tub
,lla ti daer I .ti dekil …I“
”.eluY no ffuts rof yrarbil eht ni kool
.atad fo spaeh dna spaeH .atad erom
gnisufer saw I tuB .tnaem kooL ehT tahw wenk I
dah etar traeh yM
,evirra em draeh eH
”.hsac fo tib riaf a edam I
saw ti syaw rehto lla ni tuB .egrus mraw ,tfos a ,syaw emos ni eltbuS
.emoh ta ot desu saw I gniyrp eht dekcal tI .level ym
.seil saw evol dellac yeht tahW“
,emertxe saw ti ,nrop yag
”.gniog tpek dna t’nsaw I fi niart rehtona ro ykcul saw I fi sub a dedraob nehT
”.nam a no rehto eht ro yaw eno em yaws ot gniog t’nsi rewolf A“ .dennirg dna detrons I
I dna desserdnu yawflah saw I
evah ot evah t’nod eW“
.taht htiw nokcer ot ydaer t’nsaw I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.tuo emoc dluow gnihton tub ,nepo gnignah htuom ,gniyrt tpek I
,gnirac-lla si doG hcihw yb metsys a ,ti fo em dlot
.hturt kcirb ennot-owt ,tnulb A
eh woh tuoba gnihtemos saw erehT
.nap eht ni gniliob retaw eht yb ylno detpurretni ,ecnelis ni doots eW  ”.oN“
,erif eht pu pot thgim I“ .mih fo tnorf ni lwob ytpme eht ni krof sih gnicalp ,dias selrahC
”?suovren uoy sekam ti tuoba tahW“  ”.t’nac I tuB
.swalc werd sracs yM
.nrecnoc otni detlem
gnieerf saw gnilevarT“
.mraw saw erif ehT
”.t’nevah uoY
.htmraw sih ni em
.erot yehT .tib yehT
.kniwt a ylpmis saw eh
.taorht ym ni smrof pmul A
yrtnuoc eht fo htdiw eht ssorca gnivom esuaceb deyats yehT
lufraF lacsaP yb
”.spots sub ni ffo elpoep modnar gnikcus syug eht naht efas erom raf
eH‘ .flesym ot deil I ’.won thgir no denrut yllaer ton
”.uoy seracs tahw s’tahT“
uoy …tsoor ot emoh ruoy edam ev’uoy taht
,ydob sih htiw deirub era smelborp s’nam a taht htrib morf thguat ,nem dlo raey neetenin owt rof tuB .tnulb
”?obezag a ni sgnos klof gnigniS ?sredle gniw-thgiR ?stnemugrA
.enim gniteem seye nrubua sih
”.detaert era su ekil elpoep yaw eht ,dlrow eht ni etah ehT“ .dias I
.tcidda xes sselevol
.doof rof yenom ekam ot snwot ni sboj lainem
namow a dna nam a neewteb si evoL
.3002 fo raey ffo raf eht ni dnabsuh ym llac dna yrram d’I nam eht tem d’I ,yaM nI
.taes eht ni kcab tis dna ehtaerb ot deirt I
”~traehteews olleH“
.saw nam a detseggus yteicos tahw dah I esoppus I
,elttil a tlem sdnim ruo gnittel
s’tI“  .ti kees ot deracs oot raf saw I tuB
.dehcaer I .deplug I ”.ti hcuoT“
.segaP yrruFoS dna
.naelucreh saw siht
.nem owt neewteb evol fo dnik elbatpecca-ylerab
dna gniticxe erom hcum os dekool ti ylno ,saw ti dias ylimaf ym tahw yltcaxe saw tI
.devolnu efiw a morf tpek sterceS .steliot
.liob ot ti gnittes dna retaw htiw nap a gnillif ,denialpxe I
ksir siht nekat ev’dluow I .gnihton rof yawa nur evah d’I ,xes evah t’ndid I fI
.eroc eht ot nam leets a detlem taht kool ehT
”.dlrow eht ot etaler uoy woh ni elbatrofmoc era uoy taht suolaej
.nopu deyalp saw ti elbat eht erew ew ,yad dab a nO
.rrup enipluv yrev a evag dna dennirg eH
”.eb ot ti tnaw uoy fi ylnO“
.pets ym ni gnirps a fo gnihtemos htiw wons eht hguorht degdurt I
gnikcuf ynam oot ksa yeht fi sdik rieht ta tihs worht dnA
”?su tuoba wonk sklof ruoy oD“
.noitpircsed lacisyhp
”.pu hsaw ll’I“ .dias I
.evol fo dnik lauxes ylgnisimorpmocnu ,reeuq
tsuj …htiw trats ew tuoba woH .yakO“ .deddon selrahC
,syug thgiarts neewteb sdehs ekib dniheb sbojwolb etarepseD
”.su rof sgnos klof gnis
.doG …dna ylimaf ym
.keehc ym gnikcil
.tniop siht ot pu srehcaet elbirret
.enigami nac uoy naht syaw eroM“ .sdda selrahC
.noitcelloc drocer sih hguorht gnikcilf mih ees ot ssorca dekool I
”,srac xoB“ ”?enalp a nI“
a em dellac yeht ,saw I tahw tuo dnuof ylimaf ym nehW“
”.raed ,lufrednow setsaT“
.evol otnI .erac otnI
”.duol tuo ti yas I nehw suolucidir …sdnuos tI“
.tsael ta thguat saw I woh saw tI
.em dnuora depparw smra siH
dna yknulc erew sretiuqes-non esehT .tsal ta dias selrahC ”.degnoleb I erehw wenk I hsiw I“
al À‘ dekil I taht rebmemer od I tuB
.pu kcab desae I yllautnevE
?stneserP …od ew od ,oS“
.hhu …ni detapicitrap uoY“ .deplug I
dna hsa ot nrub thgim smelborp eht gnipoh
.tuo dnif ll’yehT“
.niaga kooL ehT em evag ,dennirg dna dehsulb xof yM
.oot saw I ,nwod peed ,taht dnA .evol
.delkcuhc selrahC
”?elttaeS ot tog I woh uoy llet reve I diD“
elpoep fo dnik ruo ekil t’ndid yehT
a nrob gnieb rof ,eruliaf esnetni hcus tlef dah I
,namow a dna nam a
.em gnillet erew sesnes ym tahw mrifnoc ot nwod ecnalg suovren a koot I
.tcejbus eht degnahc I .taht htiw nokcer ot tnaw t’ndid I
.ffuts hguor ,evissecxe
.elbat eht ta staes ruo koot dna slwob owt otni atsap ruo detnaced eW  .elzzum ym rednu eson sih tup dna
tnes tI .yrtlus dna mraw ,kciht enot ,dias eH
.neppah ti ekam ot hguone evarb
.hctam ssehc taht ni snwap neeb dah sgnilbis ym dna em ,yad doog a nO
.ecar traeh ym edam ti fo aedi ehT
a dah I hcnul no elihW“
,pirg ot sdnah ruof lla esu ot stnaw ylevitcnitsni rumel A .teef ym no stoob gnikih fo riap dlo na htiw
...m’I .ni tif I ecalp a evah t’nod I“
.em dnuora desae wap siH .sdon selrahC
was tsrif I nehW
.yawa og ot desufer stug ym ni ssem gnilriws ,ylkcis tahT
saw I ,til erif eht htiW
.erif eht morf yawa ,hcuoc eht dniheb raewrednu ym dedracsid dna desserdnu I
?ti od uoy did yhW“
.delims I dna atsap eta I .llew ti dih I tuB
,ti tuoba gniklat detrats d’I woN .deksa eH
ro erocdrah taht ti od ot dilav yltcefrep s’tI
.deilper selrahC ”.dnatsrednu I“
”.oot uoy ot olleh dnA“
,won xes tuoba snoitseuq gniksa trats ot evah d’I demees tI
dna hcuoc eht no kcab em yal eh daetsnI .pots
em ekil rehtona edisgnola
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.ynohp dna etamitigelli eb dluow dah I evol yna tahT
,tsal ta dias eH ”.daed
.niaga detrulb I ”.ot tnaw I“ ”.xes
mraw yats ot tsuj tius ym revo fracs dna taoc a ni pu depparW
.tas dna seye ym deird I
.em ta kool ot gninrut ,dedda eH
saw eh taht selrahC mrofni ot detpmetta I nehw ti dezilaer ylno I
”.taht naht mrof-eerf erom rehtar s’ti lleW“
.elkcuhc suovren a evag neht ,dehgis eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
…si doG neht …gnorw si evoL
…I dna egap yreve
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.nap eht ot ti dda ot ydaer
.yltfos tub ,ylmrif
,repsihw a ta dias eH
.kcab og reven dluoc I ,ti enod d’I ecno dnA
thguoht I taht t’nsaw tI
.0791 fo hcraM ni etatS notgnihsaW ni devirra I
t’ndid yeht yhw nialpxe dluow era uoy erehw gniwonk ton mehT“
t’ndid I os 81 denrut I retfa shtnom wef a tfel I
.elgguns yzoc ,mraw a
.niaga lriws ot detrats yteixna fo tip tahT
”.stuoba ereht ro erehT
ta ti gniksa saw eH ”?tahw tuobA“
.regnis klof ,yug a wenk ylimaf ym haeY“
.t’ndid …I ,hO“ .dehsulb I
”.rehtob eht flesym evas ll’I .ton ylbaborP“
”?taht otni seog taht thguohterof dna erac fo tnuoma eht aedi yna evah uoY“ .detrons eH
.enips ym pu ssenizzuf a
,moordeb taht ni neppah ton thgim ro thgim tahw yojne uoy rehtehw ot sa sseldrageR
,nosmirC gniK yb gniK nosmirC eht fo truoC eht nI
won …dnA .edisni era uoy nam eht emoceb oT
.sgnileef ym tuoba gniklat fo elbapacni yletelpmoc dna ,hO
,nemow owt ,nem owt eb ti rehtehW .yppah si doG ,xes lausnesnoc
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
t’ndid I .spahrep ,dnik elbained ylbisualp ehT
.”’samtsirhC nagap‘ a sa ti fo snoitpircsed esool dnif yllaer ylno dluoC“ .dias I
,sevitucexe lennahc kramllaH yrgna suoirav morf nur eht no yltnerruc si ohw
.srednow dnim yM
.dnuora em desae selrahC
”amohalkaO ni em rof tuo llits ylbaborp si tnarraW
”?enut eht rebmemer uoY“
fo hsur neddus a tlef I
.lasuora ’selrahC
.skcals dna trihs ym ot nwod won ,deilper I
.yltfos dias selrahC
,tekcub a htiw denruter dna pu tog neht ,niaga em dekcil eH
elihw desuora dna dekan gnieb
.sselrewop tsomla tub
did neht dna rac xob a fo kcab eht otni delgnub tsuj I
ekil tlef taht dnuos elttil dethgiled siht ,psag
.thgirla deganam I gnitoof-erus dna kcul doog elttil a htiw tuB“
,tas I ereh tuB .toggaf
.taht tnorfnoc ot tnaw t’ndid I
.elohtihS“ .deggurhs xof ehT
”…hsiweJ ,milsuM ,naitsirhC era sklof emoS .tsiehta na er’uoY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.eno ni lla yhw nosaer eht dna htiw evol ni os llef I nam ehT
”?ecnis meht ot nekops uoy evaH“ .deddon eH
,relevart wollef ruoy
”?worromot rof nalp eht s’tahW“
”.mih tuoba em dlot yeht gnihtyreve tuo dettolb I ,em setah doG riehT
.niaga ti od ot mih detnaw I taht wenk I tub ,saw dnuos taht tahw wonk t’ndid I
dna saw ytinummoc lacol taht taerg woh tuoba erew sgnos rehto eht llA“
.ereht tog I nehw enohp ot em ksa neve t’ndiD
tog ev’I ”.em ekil er’yeht“
”’eniatnof erialc
,emat ot em rof t’nerew saes dliw esohT .ti tnorfnoc
”.meht gnoma refas leef yletinifed I
.niaga seye sih otni kool ot nrut I
.stug s’rehto hcae etah ohw
.nageb eH ”.gnillevarT“
yas dna ta kool nac uoy dlrow eht ni elpoep ,ot klat nac uoy stsiehta rehto era erehT .gnihton
.gnihtyna naht erom ot tnaw I“
”.xes emas eht ot noitcartta sti yb denifed ebirt ym
.rehte eht otni gnikool dna gnisuap
.seye ym otni derats
.ma I sa ffits sa s’eH .ecnalg I
era rehto hcae ni stsif gnittup dna snoegnud ni pu deit syug eht taht wonk ot desirprus eb d’uoY
.drazzilb a emoceb ot pu gnipahs saw llafwons eht dna ,krad ydaerla saw tI
.taoc ym fo tuo desae I sa em sdrawot deppets eH
dna moordeb ehT .nalp-nepo
.ti ta derats I dna hself sih ot derednow seye yM
repsihw a ta gnidda erofeb taorht sih gniraelc ,dias selrahC
d’eh dna dnuora tis d’ew dna yad samtsirhC erofeb os ro keew a ecalp sih ot dnuora og dluow seilimaf hcir rehto eht fo hcnub a dna flesyM
tog dna atsap eht detnaced I
.rebos saw I ,rebos erew syug eht ,ti ot detnesnoc I“ .gurhs a evag eH
tlef reven I tuB .ti rof gnihtyna naht erom ,detnaw ,detacitsatnaf ,demaerd d’I
eht tel I .kcor sa drah saw eH .rae ym ni derrup eH .ruf mraw ,toH .ruf eraB
.rebmeceD gnirud noitarbelec nagap
”.evol gniyortsed yb doG llik uoy ,nugdnah a htiw doG llik t’nod uoY“ .gniplug ,dias eH ”.seY“
dias selrahC ”.oN“ ”-I yrros m’I“
ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,syadiloH yppaH
.ees dluoc I gnihtyreve deillat I
,nemow owt dna nem eerht
,yasrep ,lavitsef eno ton s’tI“
.sdon dna selims xof yM  ”.ti devol
hcuS“  -eb d’tahT ?I dluoc ,t’ndluoc I ...sdoG ...did I fI
.tuo detrulb I ”.suovren m’I“
.eciffo ym naht emoh eht ot resolc hcum saw taht egarag a ta dekrow eH
.gniht thgir eht did uoY“
.deireuq selrahC ”?sgnos kloF“
”.enog meht detnaw I sa hcum sa tsuj enog em detnaw yeht kniht I
dluow ti ,em reggub
”.ti evah llahs ew nehT“ .sdon eH
.ruf ym hguorht hsurb
”thgiN eht esuaceB
,dloc ylsuoiciv erew cebeuQ ni sretniW
.daeh ym fo kcab eht no ssik a decalp eH .srepsihw selrahC
.atsap eht rof ecuas eht etaerc ot detrats dna nap a koot
.em fo tnorfni dnuora desae swap siH .llits dnats I dna knis
”.uoy fo dnuos eht ekil yehT“ .dias selrahC ”.seY“
.gnikrims dna gninnirg neewteb ediced ot elbanu elzzum sih
,dias eH ”.oot uoy evol I“
.denialpxe xof ehT
ni tol a ti rof em dehsinup dad yM .yltnerappa ,siht od ot desoppus t’nerew neM .tuo llaf …tsuj sdrow eht dna sehcrul tug yM
,em tsniaga debbur dna derrup eH
s’eH‘ .t’ndluoc I taht niaga dna
.mih dessik dna pu tnel I ”.evol ekil sleef ti epoh tsuj I
.tlef reve d’I evol laer tsrif eht saw ti dna
,deltit-fles s’htabbaS kcalB .eerht
”?eh saw ,evol no neek reven saw htiw pu thguorb erew uoy doG naitsirhC tahT“
.mih ot hcum os snaem htiaf s’selrahC rednow oN
.dewollof taht sliated eht
tserup eht si evoL .tniop eht
dna ekil leef thgim ti tahW
- ni yalbmerT rotciV“   yojne esaelP
.tuo elbmut sdrow erom dna niaga htuom ym nepo I
…neht litnu tuB“ .tsal ta dias eH
…dna sklof ym gnir ll’I .stneserp evah ,pu ekaW“ .deksa I
tsuj sdrow ehT .ti pots t’ndluoc I
htiw tub ,erutats ni dna noitanotni ni
.gninaelc no desucof I tub ,erif eht ot doow erom dda mih draeh I .gniod saw eh tahw hctaw
.kool mraw ,tneitap taht
htiw decalper ,enog gnol si erofeb dah eh krims ynroh tahT
,duol eht detnaw I .taht tnaw
.gniyrc saw I saw wenk I llA
.rehto hcae gnidloh er’eW
yehT“ .delkcuhc selrahC
.raewrednu sih ni neve ,erongi ot elbissopmi si doohnam siH
…tsuj s’tI .noisiced nekopsnu na s’tI
erif eht neht tuB
t’ndid I .nehctik eht ot denruter dna doots I sa ecalperif eht ot tnew dna deddon eH
.thginot neppah ot gniog saw ti dnA
,rac a droffa t’ndluoc sklof yM“ .delims eh
a m’I ekil leef I“ .dehgis eH
,eldduc a ekil ti fo knihT“ .derepsihw eH
.ti tup ot mih detnaw I erehw
evol tahw si selrahC
.mih elbuort ot mees t’ndid xes ehT
.aedi on evah I“ .deggurhs I
eht otni pord lwob dna krof
.esle enoyreve sa eno emas eht ton tuB
.yrt nac ew ,thgir sleef ti revenehW“ .dias eH
”.dlo er’uoy nehw tluciffid erom tol a si
”.raey txen spahreP
.gniziremsem saw tI .remmis
.xof ym dehctam I litnu gnisserdnu yb selbuort ym morf flesym detcartsid
.seye nrubua s’xof ym otni kcab kool I
!rehto hcae ta maercs dnA
.nis elbahsawnu na saw ti taht stnerap ym yb dlot saw I“
.stenalp etaerc ot desu ygrene yrev eht ekil sleef tI .elbapacseni
”.thginot thgin dloc
”.sruoy gnir ot dnetni uoy fi wonk t’nod I
,enot fo ylevarg elttil A
.ti sehtaol em fo traP
rebmemer yllaer t’nod I
.gniod erew stnerap ym kcuf eht revetahw naht retteb raf saw ti dnA
.nap eht ta ylluftsiw gnirats ,desuap selrahC
”?uoy t’nera ,renaelc hguoroht a
.raewrednu sih ni tsuj saw selrahC
.raef elbaplap ,lautcA
.kcolc eht ta revo decnalg dna ni atsap eht tup I
.kcoR nI s’elpruP peeD ,swap sih ni dehctulc ,dna
.ti sessim em fo traP“
”.evael saw od ot detnaw I lla
.oot ti otno denottoc eh sa ,ylteiuq yrev
.derepsihw I ”.tib a yrt …s’teL“
.rennid eraperp ot gnitrats ot nehctik eht otni gnillorts ,deksa I
.redluohs ym no daeh sih gnitser ,dedulcnoc eH
.gnisserdnu dehsinif eW  .flesym dlot I
”…s’ti uoy ton s’tI“ .timda I
fi dnA .si ereht gniht yloh
depolevne dna em degguh ,em dleh eH
.ti denesool dna swap sih ni tleb ym koot eH
.ylralucitrap toN“
.nwonk evd’yeht fi em detroba evd’yeht em dlot yehT .toggaf
.esnetni ylemertxe ro yksir ylemertxe rehtiE
emos otni nrut d’I .em emusnoc
erom werg tug ym ni ssenkcis tahT .ogitrev
.dettimda I ”.em rof
yawa gnildnik ylwols saw erif gol A
,won evah I ecneirepxe fo sraey dna thgisdnih htiw
lla moor gninid dna moor gnivil ,nehctik eht htiw moor ’gib‘ enO .esuoh nalp-nepo na saw tI
”.gnirednow er’uoy esac nI“
”.uoy rof gnihtyna dnes
.gnihton rof siht enod evah lliw uoy neht
.yreggub fo em esucca ot spoc eht dellac yletaidemmi eh ,yug a gnirusaelp retfa nehw emit eno saw ot tnesnoc t’ndid I tahW“
.nocibuR eht ssorc ot gniog saw I
.tol a part taht otni llef I shtnom ylrae eht ni tub ,taht gniod ton ta retteb tog I
.ti saw tahT .raeF ’.wonk’y
,trons desuma na evag eH
deppolf riah dlog ,kciht siH
evah elpoep nehW“ .dias selrahC
rehtaf yM .siht od em tel t’ndluow doG
”.ffuts erocdrah eht naht dilav ssel on ro erom oN .oot xes s’tahT
.roolf eht ot llef
noitats sag ni seikciuq gnidarged ,gnissarrabme ot denitsed saw em ekil reeuq A
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.gnorw gnihtemos od uoy nehw rof si ’yrroS’“
dna detrons eh ”laedi morf raF“
,skcoc wef a dekcus
”?ffuts siht lla wonk uoy od woH“
.ylimaf sih morf tces siht detirehni dah xof yM .elbillaf gnieb noitnem ot toN .tib elttil a stneve evohs ot ylno elbA
”.sehcni ruoy tsuj ton ,uoy tnaw I“
.ereht yats t’ndluoc I tub sklof ym devol I .ereht nwod
eno siht piks esaelp
,esolc deppets eH
.tekcit sub a em evag rehtaf yM .revuocnaV ni ytinutroppo boj a dah I meht dlot I
”?nam fo dnik esor a uoY“
…ro seikciuq sselevol
.rehto hcae morf evol dna smsagro gniklim
.snaej dna trihs-t sih htiw selrahC
.em fo tnorfni gol eht polevne semalf eht dehctaw I .yzzid tlef I
.seralg mrif rof tnelat a dna tius a gniraew
.smret nwo sih no eno eb dluohs eh
.ni delttes yllanif dah I ,rebmeceD yb tuB
.em ot tpecnoc neila na ekil saw tI .ytirecnis s’tI
.devirra dah wons eht raey siht tub
.em revo flesmih desae
.niaga derepsihw selrahC
,sessik ni rehto hcae ehtab
tsuj saw selrahC dlo raey neetenin emussa ylno nac I .tnaem
.stroffe ym gnitaicerppa ,em ta delims eH
”?sgnos eht fo yna rebmemer uoy oD“ .deddon xof yM
dah eH .erofeb deretnuocne d’I yna ot tnereffid yleritne saw htiaf ’selrahC .erif
”.emit sdnoces ytnewt ni
.ylimaf lacigoloib ym tuohtiw eluY tsrif ym saw sihT
.delims dna daeh sih denrut
”.rehto hcae ni sgniht suomruone gnittup snoegnud ni stiftuo suonimo ni syug ro
.evah dluoc I gnihtyna
.ecalp eht ni smoor rehto ylno eht erew moorhtab
,enitsednalc rehtie saw ti ni ffuts ylno eht dnA .dnuof ew nrop eht saw xes yag fo ecneirepxe ylno yM“
.yltcaf fo rettam yrev ,deifiralc selrahC ”?noitutitsorP“ ”...hhu
.derepsihw selrahC ”~ti s’tahT“
ot troffe on edam dna deddon eH .oot
,tis ot ,elpoep rehto teem ot ,ot og nac I euqsom a ro hcruhc a evah t’nod I
.niaga kooL ehT em sevig eH
a sa hcum sa ,on dias I fi tespu eb dluow selrahC
,skcals dna trihs eht tsuj ni elbatrofmoc
.trap tsal taht htiw elbatrofmocnu
.gel eht ta dehcuot ruf ruO
,etarepsed er’uoy esuaceb od uoy xes yella-kcab ymirg fo dnik ynA“ .delims xof ehT
naht erom ,yldab os siht detnaw I
…ot tnaw yllautca t’nseod
.lla ta yag yllautca t’nsaw I ebyaM .gnihton rof
a ebyam ,no kcab llaf ot yenom hcum taht lla evah
,dliub ni enilucsam saw selrahC
,nwal a dewom ,sngis wef a detniaP“ ”?sboj laineM“
”.si taht ,aigroeG morf yrtnuoc ssorC
,si ti kniht uoy sa doog sa t’nsi xes yag fi taht dnA
siht si ti mih htiw tuB .snoitcaretni lauxesoreteh ni ti dessim d’I taht deirrow I semitemoS .ekil tlef
.gnituohs saw I dezilaer I ”!snoitseuq
.dias I ”.uoy evol I“
”.denigami reve d’I naht nuf
.uoy desu yeht dna uoy desuba yeht ,uoy truh yehT
tlef yletulosba ti taht tsuJ
dna daeh ym esiar I ”.em ta kooL
.cebeuQ
.gniyrc saw I  .tol A
swap sih fo eno tlef I
.dnim ym hguorht dehsalf stca eht gnimrofrep ’selrahC fo egami ehT