:kcab mih dehctaw sdinac yrgnuh owT
”.gniyats era syob uoy ekil skool ,sey oS“
…s’flow kcalb eht tuoba stbuod yna dah nyrB dna samohT fI .ffur-kcen kciht krad
.ssik ’sevlow eht gnitalume eb ot gniog t’nerew yeht ,haeY
.demrifnoc odnamrA ”,yltcaxE“
.noitcere sih gnikorts dna
:swalc desu evah tsum flow ehT
?gniyfsitas os eb dluoc azzip elpmis a thguoht evah dluow ohw
.hctib a ekil mih gnitnuom flow kcalb gib a dna
”?eh si ,gnimottob ot desu ton s’eH“
,ruf nwo sih ni trofmoc sseldeeh emas eht dewohs ohw lamina gib eht ta dellevram samohT
.)erom yna rof worran oot raf saw teerts eht—wor eno tsuj(
.eciohc on dah eh :kcoc-flow eht htiw evom ot dah samohT
.thginot ereh peels syob eht tel dluohs eW“
.koob esarhp nailatI sih hguorht gnibmuht yb neht ,emag oediv a htiw flesmih detcartsid eh
”.ti sevol eh hcum woh ta kooL .ecaf s’igroc taht ta kool tuB
.elbat txen eht ta tas flow eht ,noitativni ’sigroc eht tA
,level teerts ta elihw
,lla retfa sregrubmah tseggus ot tuoba saw nyrB
,sllab derruf-yerg htaeneb
”.sevlesruoy ot swap ruoy peek d’uoy tbuod I ,letsoh a ni era uoy fi nevE .thgin tsrif rieht no peels ot thgiarts og meht fo wef yrev dnA
odnamrA—flow derruf-thgil ehT
.igroc eht hguorht erusaelp fo elppir a gnidnes emit hcae
”.ogerp ,ogerp ,ogerp“ dekcohs a htiw yawa kluks dna kcab ti ekat rodnev eht did ”!eizarG !oN“ dekrab dna deciton nyrB nehw ylno dna
.sriatspu ,tnemtrapa ruO
.worbeye na desiar samohT
,lworg detnetnoc ,gnol ,wol a htiw snikstaog eht otni delttes eH
.detnioppasid ton erew sigroc eht dna
,erom detnaw ,thgir tlef tsuj hcihw tub dneherpmoc t’ndid llits eh
,ociredeF ,flow reggib ehT
.dnuos eht ta deltsirb ruf siH
”.emoh ta deyats evah dluow I
.def syob uoy teg s’tel ,thgirlA“
flow ehT  .laitnetoP
.sehtolc s’igroc eht hguorht neve ,tlef ti woh saw tahT .mraW
rieht etipsed igroc eht otni deremmah dna
.tsaeb …deredluohs-daorb ,derruf-kcalb ,gib a ,lla meht erofeb doots ociredeF
.hctorc sih ni igroc eht gniltsen
”?uoy rof kooc reve rentrap ruoy seoD“
.dneirfyob sih naht lufrewop erom hcum os
.peed god eht delapmi dna
dna allerazzom gnitlem eht
.yawa dedaf lwoh s’odnamrA ,yllautnevE
.dlrow eht ot nevig sah yrtnuoc siht doof suoegrog eht lla fo kniht tsuJ
,htaehs s’god eht gnikcil ,sllab-igroc esoht gnitfeh ,elohliat eht morf sdrawpu eugnot daorb sih decnalg dna ,htaerb yflow mraw htiw igroc eht desaet
.odnamrA sa ,ned nwo sih ni
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.gninoitidnoc ria eht ta og tsal eno evah ot dediced eH .nwod dekcab nyrB
,erats deedni did sigroc ehT
,kcobnegeiZ yb ”…emoR ni nehW“
.kciht …saw ociredeF
,ekila rotisiv dna lacol
”.resolc emoC“ .delworg edeF
,azzip aranobrac eht evah ll’I“
.tbuod on ni meht tfel esolc pu gnisserp enipul emosdnah rednels siht ,noitatneiro
.deilper nyrB ”,taerg did eH“
,afos eht fo egde eht no dehcrep yehT
?sekoj doof eht htiw gnitrats er’uoy woN“
.sucof sti tsol dah ezag esohw
,yawrood eht ni doots ohw ,odnamrA ot denrut dna deppiy sigroc ehT  ”.oot
,ecalp ni dekcol yeht dna flow eht hguorht degrus redduhs ydob-lluf a litnu hteet sih hguorht gnilrans ,redrah dna
nevow teY .dnuora dettod erew selbat nedoow fo tnemtrossa na
,afos eht ssorca delwarc god dekan dna ykcots ,trohs eht ,plug a htiW
dneirfyob sih was eh ,seye sih nepo ot lliw eht dnuof samohT nehw ,daetsnI
,redrah tsurht ociredeF
.tnemtnetnoc fo lworg eltneg a htiw igroc eht ta kcab gnikool
”.resolc teg ot dnA“
.ydaer mih teg dna ,yppup ruoy ot pu ti ekam dluohs uoy ,yawa deirrac oot teg uoy erofeb oS
”?sey ,doof emos ekil dluow syob uoy ,thgiR“
,gnireviuq slwoj sih ,nwod igroc eht dellup odnamrA
.semit ta gniyrt eb dluoc eh tuB
.slamina derruf-kciht owt eht morf gnisir ,flow ynroh fo tnecs eht saw ti ebyaM
.moor gninid eht fo kcab eht ta rood llams a hguorht
.kool rehtona koot samohT
”,wonk t’nod I ,hO“  .odnamrA deksa
.deciton odnamrA tub ,evom elttil a—
”.peels ot og ylbaborP
.gnaf fo wohs gniwonk a htiw rood tnemtrapa eht desolc eh erofeb ,hguoht ,owt ro dnoces a rof derats ylno edeF
.tuo sessalg eht derahs eh dna ,elbat nedoow dilos a no nwod yart eht tes flow ehT .saw fo dnik ti
.flesmih hcuols on saw edeF
”.sdnema ekam ot yaw tnellecxe na si azzip eerf
a dnuora yaw sih wenk ylbaborp
.syob ,sevlesruoy nialpxe ot evah t’nod uoY“
.yppup ykcul a tahw
.letsoh ruo ot kcab daeH“ .deilper nyrB
.enipul gib eht
,swap s’samohT otni tellaw adraP rehtael citnehtua laer a dehsup
,elttil yb elttil ,erom dna erom ni flesmih gnikrow
saw sihT      ”.ykcul
,liat sih rednu dna pu degdun toh dna mrif gnihtemoS
,reggib hcum oS .saw enipul eht
,samohT deilper ”,eciN“
.htgnerts sih dethgilhgih dna elcsum s’enipul eht demarf hcihw
,doof naciremA paehc emos detnaw I fi ,si tniop yM“ .tiab eht gnikat rehtob neve ot pu def oot saw nyrB
”.enob a yppup a evig s’tel nehT“  ”.od I …I“  ”.oot taht ekil uoy dnA“
”.ereh tsomla s’doof eht ,nuh ,yrrow t’noD“
.odnamrA dias ”,deedni era yehT“
…s’odnamrA etipsed teY ,htaehs derruf tfos a fo pils eht htiw railimaf naht erom saw samohT
.ria looc eht ot ruf sih fo erom desopxe flow eht sa
.tsrif eht dniheb pu emac flow dnoces a nehw
slacol eht htiw detniauqca teg ot gnitcepxe t’nsaw I“
,samohT dnuora rethgit sgel sih depparw flow ehT  ”…ruoy leef …nac I“
,suoiciled dna yffulf
.em ta skool edeF woh yltcaxe s’tI
.tut a htiw detpurretni flow nael ehT
.sseug I ,noitpo na s’ti
”.oot tuo mih gnikcehc uoy was I ,no emoc hO“  ”…emosdnah …s’eH“
,seseehc ettal id roif
.srae rieht gnippord ,dehgis sgod htob dna
.hteet etihw prahs htiw gninnirg
.rof gnikool erew sigroc eht ngis eht saw ereht dnA
.seohs dna stekcaj rieht dehctid sigroc ehT  ”.taes a ekat
”?ti si raf woh ,neht thgirlA“
.euqsurb oot dnuos t’ndid eh depoh nyrB
.flow on m’I tub ,haeY“
nyrB elihw ,noitats inimreT edistuO
.etarebiled ot sigroc eht tfel odnamrA  ”.sriatspu
”?yawaekat ygdod emoS
,tniat s’igroc eht revo pit-kcoc derepat sih debbur dna
,denway dna tuo dehcterts eH .edis sih otno gnillor erofeb
.retnuoc eht ot yaw sih edam eh dna ,sigroc eht deciton trihs s’fehc a ni flow derruf-kcalb egral a ,nehctik eht nI
,tsetnoC yrotS trohS yrrufoS 1202 eht fo renniw eht saw eH
gib woh fo kniht ot ton deirt
.sserdnu ot detrats dna pu doots nyrB litnu ,swap dettab dna delims sigroc ehT .troffe on ot txen htiw ,sdrawkcab mih dellup odnamrA
.muminim eht ot erutarepmet eht derewol eh ,walc a fo spat kciuq htiW
.ekatsim on dna ,emoh flow a saw sihT .sniks lamina
”?eiP ooL weD …airezziP
.delbmurg nyrB  ”.nailatI si
.srae s’samohT dehcaer rrum railimaf A
.deddon nyrB  ”?gniggalF“
,moor eht decap nyrB
yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht htiw krow gnimocpu sah osla eH
yrrufoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,edis sih no degnuol flow eht ,lasuora suoivbo
.nrut ni trihs s’fehc sih fo nottub hcae denepo ociredeF ,swalc fo kcilc a htiW
.sllaw eht ot derutseg igroc ehT  ”.yaw yreve nI
.oot snaf eht ffo tuhs esruoc fo hcihW
.reed fo sreltna eht dna ylatI larur fo sgnitniap dewohs sllaw eht elihw
.ecnatsid eht desolc nyrB elihw
lamina hcae ,skcil tew ,gnilworg ,yppah emos derahs senipul eht dna
”.siht hctaw ot tnaw thgim uoy ,syoB .detrats gnitteg tsuj er’ew ,edeF ,yrrow t’noD“
.hsibbur decudorp-ssam ,ytilauq-wol emos tae ot tsuj ,ereh yaw eht lla nwolf ton evah I
.lamina gnikrul ,gib eht morf regnuh fo lworg eht raeh dluoc eh ,edeF ees ton dluoc eh hguoht dnA .nikstaog a otno gnippird dna tcere ,flow eht odnamrA ,mih ediseb dnA
noos saw flow denrettap ehT
.ebul eht rof lufetarg saw samohT ,emas eht llA
rof eno dna ,ssenippah rof eno ,htlaeh rof eno
…gnikool-yldneirf ,gnilims-tfoS
.mhM“  ”.regrubmah a teg tsuj t’ndid ew dalg m’I .noos os
.taem-flow nellows drah s’ociredeF no gnibbur ssenffits yggod s’nyrB ,enipul dna eninac ,rehtegot dellor yehT
.esnopser ni borht yvaeh a tlef dna ,dehctiwt samohT
.nepo dekcilc tnemtrapa eht ot rood eht ,tnemom taht tA
,hguoht ti tlef slamina htoB
.erutan fo sehcuot elttil erew erutinruf siht tsgnoma ni
,sretfar eht morf steksab ni gnuh dna dnuora doots stnalP
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
”?sseug I ,nic niC“ .nyrB dias
,yffuts a eb ot tuo denrut ’moor muimerp‘
:ssalg hcae ni eerhT“
,pot eht ta rood rehtonA
,seye desolc-flah hguorht etam rieht ni erusaelp eht gniees
.rehto hcae ta kool uoy yaw eht ees I“
”.gninrom worromot muessoloC
.sigroc eht ot denrut eH
,niaga samohT dniheb delttes flow ehT
,sehcruhc elbram dna sesuoh dna
.sigroc evitcepser rieht ta yawa dekrow yeht elihw neve
.kcab sih gnikorts ,wap s’flow a tlef samohT
.nepo mih gnimaer yletinifed tsom tub
,ni desolc ociredeF  .lamina giB
,noitcafsitas fo lworg a
.kcirt eht gniod noitcere derepat s’flow eht fo leef eht ,ffuh lautum A
”.taht ekil sresuort ruoy ni gniniarts ,elbatrofmoc eb t’nac tI“
.syart rieht tcelloc ot denruter odnamrA ,laem eht retfA
.knird sih fo erom gnippis
.sdnuos kcils fo tsethgils eht htiw igroc eht detartenep flow ehT
ytiniffaruF dna
.lawardhtiw wols a nageb eh erofeb
.serutcip eht yb gnigduj ,staes wef a tog ev’yeht ,lleW“
rehgih sehctip wef a lwoh taht gnisiar
,riah draug naht erom elttil
,erom ecno deppots odnamrA dna
.ebul rof loord-flow ylno htiw dnA .era yeht decneirepxe woh rettam oN
saw ereht teY .tlep sih fo erac doog ekat ot dah flow ehT
.liat-rednu s’igroc eht tsniaga htgnel elohw sih gniyal dna
”?dnuora gnidnats tsuj taht evah uoy desirprus ton I ma yhW“
,samohT ot denrut nyrB
.nehctik eht ot ylbamuserp ,rood edis a hguorht gnidaeh
.seye sih dellor samohT
.gniyrt saw dneirfyob sih tsael tA
…a fo gnihtemos evah od syug esohT
.lworg eht gniod s’eh won ,thguoht samohT ,taerg hO .delworg nyrB
eht ni degnid lleb a ,retal setuniM
.llaw eht no sreltna emos ta decnalg eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.diulf kciht ylralimis ,raelc ylralimis a gnippird flow eht ta dekool igroc ehT .elohliat s’igroc eht ot wap sih thguorb eH
.samohT rof edanomel ,nyrB rof ztirps lorepa—sknird rieht deredro dna staes rieht koot sigroc ehT
”.egasuas flow nailatI citnehtua emos taeb t’naC
?rof diap erew sweiver esoht fo ynam woh dnA
”.em htiw enif s’taht dnA .od I
.ni thgir dekcut dna
,llams s’lamina gnilworg eht htiw emit ni evom dna flow kcalb eht ot dleiy dneirfyob sih dehctaw samohT
.ffins ot deen neve t’ndid eh—eson s’samohT ot esor deesina fo tnecs mraw ehT
,flow eht dehctaw samohT
odnamrA t’nsaw ti tub
azzip tsael ta dnA
…metsys dnuos gnikool-lufrewop a ,noisivelet A
”?ti t’nsi ,thgis tnasaelP“
.meht tih tsomla dna renroc a dnuora dezzub apseV a nehw )yllaretil tsomla( stibah gnivird namoR ni esruoc-hsarc a dah sigroc eht ,nehT
knird sih deppis nyrB ,troter sih fo thguoht samohT elihW
.thgin eht rof nwod gnidniw saw
”,yhs eb ot deen oN“
,liat denrut dna delims odnamrA
”.inoreppep eht ekil d’I dnA“  ”.esaelp
.steerts eht no kcab erew sigroc eht ,retal setunim eviF
.rood eht dniheb uoy dellems I“
.ezorf dna …afos eht ta revo dekool eH
,nehctik eht ni drah gnikrow ,yad lla pu taht tliub evah tsum flow ehT
.rrum elttil a htiw seye sih desolc eh dna
,samohT brutsid naht rehtaR
esoht xim ot ton wonk I ,seigolopa yM“
peed a ni gnikat ,peed ni dehtaerb eh
.pu detnuom edeF nehw meht denepo noos eH
.liat sih deggaw odnamrA
.ruovas ot gnihtemos saw siht
”.erehwemos nwod tis ot referp llits d’I tuB
”?leef ti seod woh dnA“
.pmur ot wap htiw ecalp ni igroc eht dleh odnamrA tub ,pu kcab ot saw tcnitsni s’samohT
.elbat-edis ybraen a ot revo dehcaer dna samohT desaeler odnamrA
wap eno gnirewol erofeb
,ociredeF si yug gib siht dna ,yaw eht yb ,odnamrA m’I
.pu ekops samohT nehw
.sreksihw sih ni elgnit tnasaelp a tup
.noitca otni derrihw snaf eht dna yalpsid eht no pu til ”C°03“
,trams—dnoces eht yb erom flow siht gnikil erew yehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.nossel nailatI utpmorpmi rehtona rof doom on ni saw nyrB tuB
,yako saw igroc eht taht gnikcehc
.eizarg ,wA“  .deddon flow gib ehT  ”?pu gnikcol thgirla uoY .tnemtrapa ruo syob eht wohs ot gniog m’I“
,samohT htaenrednu koohs afos ehT
”?gnikooc s’doof ruoy elihw uoy nioj I fi dnim …eton taht no oS
liat sih tsap evird ot gninetaerht ,dellews ssenkciht wen a nehw
,edisa sllab-god sih gnigdun
.dessorc redrob worran eht
.eganam reve dluoc dneirfyob sih naht repeed mialc a gnivael lamina eliriv eht
.dootsrednu flow gib eht dna
.gnippirD .gnihctiwT
,wols a nageb odnamrA ,esuap taht nI
”.mih tuoba trohs s’taht elttil yrev s’ereht ,em tsurt tuB .trohs rof edeF
.nwod raewrednu dna sresuort sih dils eh elihw spil sih gnikcil
”…gnitar rats 7.4 ,nevo azzip reporP
.gnilggurts ,gniredduhs saw nyrB ,seY .deednI
htaenrednu selbat gninid fo wor a htiw hcae ,teerts eht otni tuo dettuj sgninwa
.knalf nwo sih ta swap tlef eh ,dehctaw samohT elihW
.elzzum nepo sih ssorca nettirw saw erusaelp eht tuB
.rewsna ot detatiseh samohT teY
”.yojne ,syob ,og uoy ereH“
”.noitats niart eht ta kcab ecalp regrubmah a
.dezafnu ,deunitnoc odnamrA .drow elballys-evif eht ta denediw seye ’sigroc ehT ”?gnitaunisnI“
…etib tsrif sih koot samohT
.sehcnuah sih delffuhs
.yvaeh dna wol gnitser sllab enipul dna htaehs sih ,flow dekan yppah a
,hsrah erew slworg siH
.seson eninac rieht ot gnitfird ruovalf eht ta delims sigroc htoB
”…ssuf on ,ylemoh ,nredoM
,lla dna tonk ,dneirfyob sih gnillif tsaeb taht fo egami latnem eht dna ,kcoc retsnom s’flow eht fo yromem ehT
.deppord waj s’nyrB
…inoreppep ykoms ytaem eht ,ecuas otamot ybreh hcir eht
,desuora dna ffits llits tey ,kcap eht yb thguac yerp ekil gnileeF
,secneterp pu gnipeek ni tniop elttil saw ereht gnirugif dna ,lohocla eht morf zzub eltneg a gnileeF
.gnuh erom hcum os tub ,nwo s’igroc eht ot esolC
,tnetop dna drah ,mih tlef samohT
!renoitidnoc ria gnikrow a dna
.gur denrettap kciht a htiw derevoc ,roolf nedoow A
.eb ot tlep s’flow a denigami eh ekil esraoc ton ,tfos saw ruf ehT
nehw no emoc ot demees ylno snaf eht tub ,snoitpo eht hguorht gnilcyc setunim net tneps dah nyrB .lenap
.tneced ytterp skool ecalp siht ,yllautcA“
taht s’ti“ ,samohT dias ”,looc hO“
eb ot deraeppa tahw dna
”?steerts eht otno tuo kcab syob gnuoy yrgnuh eseht frut ot gniog erew uoy em llet t’nod esaelP“
,gniraeh doog dnA“  ”.egatnavda ezis
.god gninaom eht otni dekcub dna detnurg eh elihw igroc eht gnihctulc edeF
,esimorp dleh eglub tahT
,nailatI nrael ot tpmetta s’nyrB
,daeh sih deppid flow eht
.eson-ot-eson rehto hcae gnicaf ,sevlow laref owt dewohs airezzip eht edistuo ngis ehT
lortnoc s’renoitidnoc ria eht ot gnidrocca ,suisleC seerged xis-ytnewt gnilfits a ydaerla saw moor ehT
,lanoitidart erom gnihtemos tnaw uoy fi rO ?reeB
,nottub rewop eht desserp eH
.ssengnihton yhtaerb otni yawa deliart ylper s’igroc ehT
ecnartne tnemtrapa lanoisacco eht dna ,spohs elttil ykriuq ,stnaruatser ot revo denrut level dnuorg eht dna
”…uoy llet em tel tuB .taerG“
.52 dedeecxe erutarepmet eht
,srettuhs nedoow htiw denroda swodniw level-reppu rieht ,teerts eht deknalf sesuoh yerots-evif detniaP
,seye sih ssorca yerg ot nworb morf edaf a ,elzzum etihW
.desolc seye sih dna gnillol eugnot sih
,flow eht otno sretrauqdnih sih evord eh dna
,afos eht no kcab dekcik edeF
.liated yreve ni gnikat ,ned nabru ’sevlow eht dessorc sigroc eht
”.deraperp eb syawlA“ .delkcuhc odnamrA
”.uoy sa emosdnah sa ton s’eh ,naem I .si eh ,haey ,yakO“
”.desserdrevo yrev era seippuP“ .gnirrum
.lwoh enipul sselemahs a htiw tseuqnoc sih gnicnuonna dna god eht gnilapmi
,llits tnew eh dna ,mih otni pmub lamina eht tlef samohT
”?redro ot ydaer syob uoy era ,oS“
.revo koot erusaelp eht ,tsurht yreve htiw tub ,ekatsim on ekam ,truh llits tI .erusaelp mraw a ot dedleiy noitartenep eht fo nrub ehT
.sigroc eht morf elkcuhc a tog tahT
”?yadiloh ruo otni noos os thgif ot ton yrt
.yawyna ,yrt a htrow s’ti kniht I
,esenalim alla ottosir ,aranobrac atsaP
rieht ,letsoh rieht dehcaer yllanif yeht nehw dnA
,mU“ .htob meht rof gnirewsna erofeb ,samohT htiw derrefnoc nyrB
.gnihsilbuP sirneF htiw dna
,llew ,meht brutsid ew fi dnA .thgin lla
.nemodba sih ot wap ,depsag-flah samohT
,spets-wap wols htiW
tuo enog evah dluohs ew wenk I
”?won snalp ruoy era tahw ,oS“
.hsilgnE ni dna yletaidemmi ,ylper eht emac ”,yrros m’I ,hO“
.letsoh paehc emos naht recin eb ot sah tnemtrapa ruo dna ,etal s’tI
.ecalp ni mih dleh htgnel enipul kciht taht elihw neve samohT gnikcor sehcnuah lufrewop
.derrum dna derevihs god elttil ehT
”.hsleW er’ew ,yllautcA“  ”.semitemos
”.duol era sevlow uoY .aohW“
.htaehs sih morf degreme kcoc enipul kcils taht fo eroM
,syart latem owt gniyrrac ,deraeppaer odnamrA ,retal stnemoM
,detlit daeh sih ,denaom nyrB
”.pu uoy nekow tsuj evah dluohs I .reilrae
.ipuL euD ia airezziP
”.desolc si ybraen erehwyreve tuB .gnikool ma I“
,yaw eht del odnamrA
.)emit emas eht ta ylerar hguoht( drows dna nep htob sdleiw ohw taog a
?ovitsegid a tuoba woh
.ruf otni gnisserp swalc
eno siht piks esaelp
rekwah-teerts a ,enohp sih no snoitcerid pu dekool
gnireviuq swap tnorf sih ,desolc seye ,dewam-nepo denaom ohw ,etam sih ta dekool osla samohT
,esaelP .ytic gib eht ni ynacsuT fo ecils elttil ruo ot emocleW .syob ,itunevneB“
.ekat ot yug a rof kcoc-flow a fo lleh a s’taht ,em tsurT“
,elzzum nwo sih dekcil odnamrA
,owt eht fo denifed erom eht saw odnamrA elihW
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
afos eht otni deirub elzzum htiw
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
.renoitidnoc ria detsub a dna
knird sih deplug odnamrA
.liat god thgit ni kcoc flow gib
.tsrif swap tnorf ,afos eht otno gniklats erofeb
.tnemeticxe s’dneirfyob sih ta gniffuh dna gnilims ,nyrB dneirfyob sih
.nep dna dapeton a tuo gnillup erofeb ,sknird rieht nwod tes dna retal stnemom denruter odnamrA
?knird ot esle gnihtemos uoy teg I naC“
,nyrB ta delims samohT ,tfel odnamrA nehW .nehctik
,sgnidliub eht pu werg seniV
.edisni noitcere sih fo pit eht tpek ylno odnamrA
.thgit snaej nwo sih ,taes sih ni gnitsiwt saw ohw ,nyrB ta ssorca decnalg samohT  ”.uoy fo llA
,ti fo erus saw eh ,gnitalucaje flow eht tlef samohT .eit
,mlohkcotS fo edis siht erutinruf kcap-talf etihw tsepaehc eht
,mH“  .airezziP 'sevloW owT
.llits tnew god elttil ehT
.gniliec desopxe eht dna roolf eht hctam ot ,sllaw eht no slenap nedooW
.htaerb sih hctac ot gniyrt ,delkcuhc samohT
.moor erots a fo tuo eson sih dekop flow kcalb ehT
srac dekrap tsap ,steerts edis worran nwod ,taht dna yaw siht yaw rieht detsiwt yeht ,spam enohp rieht yb dediug ,os dnA .yrgnuh llits erew sgod eht teY
hguohtlA .selur eht gniwollof ylno s’eH
occesorp gnilkraps dna slacinatob rettib eht—
” .raf os yadiloh taerg gnikcuF“ .deffuh nyrB
.kool ot deen neve t’ndid eh—dehtaehsnu saw flow eht wenk samohT .dnirg yvaeh
.dneirfyob sih ta delims samohT
thgim ew …ot detnaw uoy fi tuB
.flow kcalb gninilcer eht no gniyl ,gniffuh
,niaga enohp sih pu til samohT
.sgel rieht neewteb seglub eninimef-nu rehtar emos evah did yeht ,revewoH
,dehctaw samohT dna odnamrA elihW
.semitemos etilop oot era syug hsilgnE uoY .tey tsuj pohs pu tuhs t’nevah eW .esruoc fO“
,tnorf s’flow eht derevoc ruf yerg ,eniF
,kcobnegeiZ yb ”…emoR ni nehW“
.detresed tnaruatser eht dnif ot desirprus oot saw igroc rehtieN
”…elpoep eseht ot gniyas …saw I .sey ,mU“
…wonk uoy esoppus
.rewoP .ruf taht rednu htgnerts
,repmihw a derettu samohT dna ,lamina ,citnarf
,gel reppu s’igroc eht detfil odnamrA
.ksum eht fo tnecs
.neercs enohp s’dneirfyob sih ta decnalg dna revo dedaeh nyrB ,emas eht llA
.hctorc s’edeF htiw
.dehctiwt flow eht teY
.krow flow eht tel samohT oS
,gniliec eht ni wodniw llams elgnis a htiw ,sriats fo sthgilf ruof pu citta til-ylmid
.gnilims llits saw odnamrA tuB
.tnew eh sa steehs-unem egral owt gnibbarg
”.yaw eht yb ,erats ot emoclew er’uoY“
flow gib eht ta derats sigroc ehT
.stsaerb on dah sevlow eseht
.srae sih neewteb dna no nworb ynwat thgirb a dna
,etam sih ot revo denael flow eht ,mhtyhr a otni delttes dah odnamrA ecnO
”?mhM“ .ylipeels tsomla ,pu dekool flow ehT  ”?odnamrA …mU“
,mhM“   .dneirfyob gnizod sih koohs samohT ”?taht
,xaler ot deirt igroc ehT
.pup ykael a si edeF taht ykcuL
meht dnuora ytic eht ,ylwolS
,flow fo hcni retfa hcni
.samohT no noitcere sih gnibbur dna sigroc eht htiw deltsen odnamrA ta gnirats
.liat s’igroc eht rednu gniknis
…lamina siht rof liat detfil reve edeF fI
”?nepo eb yam taht esle erehwemos
,tnorf eht ot gnippils ,wap s’flow eht neeb evah t’ndluoc tI
”?erus er’uoy fI“ .deilper nyrB ”,esaelp sey ,rE“
llits reduol derepmihw neht
eh nehw dnA .deffuh dna ,desuap
.teerts delbboc ,worran ,gnol a otno denrut yeht litnu
”.yaw siht thgir ,sigroc ,neht yakO“
”…emoR ni nehW“   yojne esaelP
,mu ,ym esucxe ot evah ll’uoY“
…doog yna saw azzip eht fi ,woN
.pot no azzip a htiw hcae
.wap a htiw snoihsuc eht otni kcab s’igroc eht gnisserp dna dnuora htob meht gnillor ,thgit nyrB dleh eH
,edisa ssalg sih tes dna
.yap ot drac tiderc sih deppat nyrB dna ,llib eht revo dednah odnamrA ,deraelc erew syart eht retfA  ”.ma yllaer I“
”!gnivrats m’I“  kcobnegeiZ yb
.taht htiw eugra t’ndluoc samohT
,retal tnemom a denruter flow ehT
.slamina giB“ .delbmur odnamrA
,evissimbus sih rof nrecnoc fo tuo spahrep dnA
.daeh sih detlit edeF ”?frA“   ”.ydaer
.afos eht yb elip a ni tfel ylralimis ,dewollof snaej siH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
gnipleh suoreneg a ni derevoc erew sazzip htob dna
”.lliw ew wonk uoY .sdrawretfa retteb leef htob ll’eW
.rewsna t’ndid samohT
,kciht dekool sesab ehT
.ativ eclod al neeb yltcaxe t'ndah
”.acubmas s’tI .knird siht wonk I“
.redrah tsurht flow eht gnittel ,peed gnihtaerb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
snoihsuc ni derevoc ,afos daorb a yb pu nekat saw tnemtrapa eht fo ertnec ehT
”.nepo erehwemos eb ot tog
htob er’eW“ .delkcuhc nyrB
,flow eht otni deltsen dna
.rehto hcae ot txen
.tsurc a tfel igroc rehtieN
dna seye sih gnisolc
,krab hgih a sserppus ot deliaf dna deirt samohT
.ruf sih tub gnihton
.roolf eht ot ti deppord dna ,daeh sih revo trihs-T sih deppils eH .yart eht no ssalg ytpme-raen sih gnittes
”.sevlow-ehs era esoht kniht t’nod I …I ,moT“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
ti hO“ .rood airezzip eht ta saw samohT tuB
,hguorht deklaw yeht nehw dna
,thgit dleh enipul ehT
”.ytriht ni esolc yehT .kciuq eb tseb d’ew tuB
”…uoy era tahw …tahW“
.ecalp siht ekil I“
,dehctiwt lamina eht erehw ,edisni repeed kcoc taht gniraeps dna
.smra sih otni god trohs eht gnikat
,afos eht ssorca delwarc samohT
.yltfos gnirons ,deb elbuod drah eht no nwod depmulf dneirfyob sih dnif dna nruter ot ylno
.sdap wap sih gnirevoc
,denosaer samohT ,hcihw—dlrow eht ni gniht larutan tsom eht saw ytidun ekil ned sih hguorht devom rotaderp ehT
s’ereht …etarepsed er’ew fi“
”.yawyna ,evom tonnac seippuP“ .deggurhs dna niaga eye sih desolc edeF  ”.letsoh
.kcab s’igroc eht gnikorts
”.yad eht ffo dnuor dna laem ruoy ffo hsinif ot gnihtemoS
wap sih dehctiwt samohT
raeh uoy ,nyrB yeH .htob uoy knaht“
.dniheb elbisiv nehctik eht htiw ,retnuoc doof a saw edisnI
”.tseb eht netfo era slaem elpmis ehT
.retteb erehwemos evah tsuj
”.won gnisolc era secalp tsoM .yrroS“
.kcab htaehs sih dils dna
neesnu kcoc flow eht ta
,revewoh ,sriatspu gnidaeh erofeB .thgiled s’flow eht ot hcum ,noisiced rieht odnamrA llet ot tnew yehT .citta gnitsaor taht naht retteb saw gnihtynA
htiw dexaler flow eht erofeb ,niaga dehctiwt
.denediw seye ’sigroc ehT
.selzzum ot sessalg desiar sdinac eerht ehT  ”.syob ,nic niC“
dluow tsurht dnoces taht taht wenk eh esuaceb tub ,htgnerts ni hctamsim rieht fo esuaceb ylno toN
?ew t’nevah ,etal oot ti tfel ev’eW“
,ydob sih hguorht gnidaerps erofeb ,eugnot s’samohT no delgnit htmraw ehT
.su dnuora ton ylniatreC .era uoy ohw edih ot evah t’nod uoy oS
.emoR ni thgin tsrif ruoy kram ot ecalp citnamor tsom eht yldrah si letsoh paehc a hguohT
.ylatI ni ma I .nuH“
.kciht ylevisserpmI
…thgit igroc eht dleh ,delims
.ytiC lanretE eht ot syob eht thguorb tahw dna
”.flow ykcul a er’uoy
”.gnivrats m’I ,edisni teg s’teL .rettam t’nseod
”.doog sdnuos taht ,esaelp sey
?elbissop taht si woH“
.nrettap eht ot noitageirav erom htiw ,derruf-thgiL
.sllebrood dna sexob tsop htiw
.elohliat eht ot kcab gnivid erofeb noitcere s’nyrB ot spal emos htiw gnihsinif dna
…siht woN .erusaelp ni seye sih desolc dna
”!…uoykna…a…hT“  ”.kcul dooG“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.flesmih dehtaehsnu igroc eht dah
,yad taht yenruoj rieht tuoba deklat sigroc ehT
,dexaler eh os dnA .etarepooc ot evah dluow eh ,xamilc hcaer ot gniog saw lamina eht fi ,wenk eh tey dnA
,deb eht morf eciov a emac ”,yakO“
,nehctik eht rof dedaeh odnamrA nehW  ”.def
,thgit igroc eht dleh odnamrA  .suoirolG  .oowA  …eb
rep olovat nu etevA .ares anouB“  .drawrof deppets nyrB os ,hguoht ,tae ot ereht erew sigroc ehT ?tonk
dehsilbup neeb sah krow sih dna
.dedda odnamrA ”,eurt yreV“
.sgnippot dna eseehc fo
.reteiuq saw ciffart eht dna ,won dnuora elpoep rewef erew erehT
.derepsihw odnamrA
flow ehT .tnap gnignah-eugnot a htiw ezag s'flow eht thguac eh dna
gnidaenk dna gnildnof
”?erovaf rep ,enosrep eud
level eson sih gnignirb
”.taht lla dna dyh o amY .pu owt
.flow gnitiaw eht fo ecarbme eht otni
.sekorts-walc ta detlem yllacitcarp dneirfyob sih taht wenk samohT
,nyrB ees ot pu dekool eH
,tnet ot detrats ydaerla dah sresuort s’flow ehT
taht otni delzzun dna ,redluohs s’flow kcalb eht no wap a decalp eH
,raelc a depmup odnamrA .resnepsid-pmup egral a saw ti nO
.eurt yreV“ .dennirg odnamrA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”…alletaiccarts id otaleg
.tleb s’samohT rednu walc a gnippils ,odnamrA dedda ”,era yeht tahT“
t’nod I“ ,flow eht deksa nyrB
,yaw-trap tnecs s’flow eht thguac eH
swap sih pu dekcik igroc eht
,riahc gninid ybraen a ot trihs sih dessot eh sa noos sa dna
.thgit oot ssalg sih hctulc ot ton gniyrt
,lleW“  ”.ffo emit emos teg ew noisacco erar eht nO .semitemoS“
eht rof dekoob stekcit tog ev’eW .haey …mU“
.stnetnoc sti gniyduts dna ssalg sih pu gnidloh saw ,elihwnaem ,nyrB
?ecalp siht tuoba woH“
,rood dnoces a dehcaer yeht ,srodirroc dellaw-erab ,til-ylmid ,worran emos hguorht gnitsiwt retfA
.cissalc a s’ti ,yeH“  .debbir nyrB ”,suorutnevdA“
.lufyalp ,emosdnah
.yawyna ,tey toN .daeha gnirewop
”?snaeb eeffoc …eseht erA“
.kcab erab s’nyrB pu wap a gniliart ,moor eht ssorca deklats edeF ,pmur-
.sucof sih nekorb evah dluow odnamrA morf noitarelecca neddus eht ,weiv raelc a teg dluoc eh fi neve tuB .seippup dna esimorp htiw gnihctiwt dna gnihctiwt
.derats sigroc eht dna ,no sthgil eht dekcilc odnamrA
.mih edisni gnibborht ,kcoc s’odnamrA fo eniltuo eht leef dluoc eh erows eH
.yrgnuh yawa stseug ruo dnes tsomla did uoy ,edeF ,woN“ .redluohs s’etam sih deppat odnamrA
…hctorc s’flow eht otni desserp yllautca
?sevlesmeht reed eht netae dah sevlow dehtoot-prahs eht ebyaM
morf elbmur yppah a gniward ,edeF htiw seson debbur odnamrA  ”.ebab uoy evoL
”.esolc ot tuoba era eW“
.tneb eb ot edam era selur
.skool sa tnatropmi sa si noitasrevnoc hguohT
erusaelp a htiw dekcarw ,samohT
,dekcub dna ,dekcub eH
elihw ,llaw eritne na pu koot flehskoob gnol A
.snat ,sdlog ,snworb :sruoloc larutan fo yrtsepat a saw tnemtrapa ehT
,nyrB htiw gniltsen semit ynam sih morF
s’erehT .gnikool peek tsuj ,neht eniF“
.deilper nyrB ”,era erus eW“
”.pleh t’now yppup a ekil gninihw ,lleW“
.gnideeccus neht dna gnir-
,esuoh-fo-tnorf yaw sih edam—
?od nac ew tseb eht taht si ,wonk t’nod I“
?maerc eci otaleg t’nsI“
.rentrap ssenisub
.weiv otni deppils ydaerla dah enipul eht fo htgnel doog A
,snoihsuc eht otni deltsen eH
,dennirg ,gnirats nyrB thguac eH
…sgnippot eht dnA .noitcefrep ot dekooc saw ,srehto ni thgil dna secalp emos ni psirc ,esab ehT
.doof emos dnif em tel esaelp …nyrB“
.emoR ni selpuoc fo tol a teg eW“ .delkcuhc odnamrA
”.taht naht laitnatsbus erom gnihtemos deen ew kniht I
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
nehw ediw tnew seye sih dna
.klaw ’setunim neetfiF“
,tnemom eht ruovas ot tsuj ebyam ro
”?od edeF did woh ,oS“
”,ti evol I“  ”.ytirepsorp
.nyrB dneirfyob sih devol samohT  ”!emoR ni er’eW
.llits redrah mih edisni lamina eht dna drah kcoc-god sih
”.oot ,etuc ytterp s’flow taht dnA“
”.xaler ot evresed lla ew dna ,sgod elam ,sgod lla era eW
,secils tsrif rieht pu dekcip ,odnamrA deknaht yehT
”.ecalp ni em gniyt flow a tog ev’I ykcul er’uoY
,wap rehto sih otni diulf gnikool-ykcits
”?yawathgiartS“
.meht no ro—sdnalsi eht edistuo noitcnitsid taht edam enoyreve toN
.tuo dessap tsomla samohT taht dedworc os saw tropria eht morf niart ehT
.elkcub tleb sih denetsafnu edeF
,pleh dna enohp sih teg ot tuoba saw nyrB dna
.eye eno denepo flow kcalb ehT ”.edeF .yeH“  .keehc s’etam sih kcil ot revo denael flow eht nehw neve ,reve sa nellows sa deyats tonk s’odnamrA
,meht gnidaerps dna gnitfil ,sgel s’nyrB gnikaT
.dneirfyob sih ta dennirg samohT
.sriats fo thgilf a saw hcihw dniheb
”?ecnelis ni gnireffus ,ereht gnittis tsuj fo daetsnI ?uoy t’ndid yhw ,lleW“
.ngis eht ta derats nyrB tuB
”.lobmys ytic rieht ekil fo dnik s’ehs os ,ytic eht dnuof depleh ehs yas yehT .lobmys flow-ehs
.etam sih ot dellac odnamrA
.worbeye na desiar flow ehT
ew nac ,nyrB ,ekas ’ssendoog rof hO“
.stsurht mrif tey ,ydaets
,selkcuhc yrgnuh ,mraw sih fo rehtona evag odnamrA
.noitaicnunorp gnorw eht eb ot dah tahT
.retaw mraw sih gnippis
,swap sih ot esor dna dewollaws samohT ,emas eht llA .igroc drah eht
,sllab sih rednu wap ,llits flesmih dleh flow ehT
noitcere der krad fo tnih tserab taht ees ,kcoc-flow taht ees dluoc eh dehsiw samohT
,niaga ekawa saw samohT woN
.ruf dna swap sih fo spit eht ot thgir
.etib ron krab rehtien dluoc ohw god a fo dnuos tnetopmi eht ,dnuos god-elttil a hcus saw tI
lwoh t’nod ew sa gnol sa ,dnim t’nod meht fo tsoM .setam era ew wonk yehT ?sruobhgien ruO“   ”?…tuoba tahw tuB“
,srewohs lanummoc eht ot ffo degdurt dah igroc eht ,retaw fo tuo gninnur dna ,gnitnap ,toH
.saw ti suoiciled yletulosba dna hcir woh nevig
raf os yrtnuoc eht fo ecneirepxe rieht tub ,oga sruoh wef a ylatI ni devirra ylno dah sigroc ehT
.erom neve gnitsaor meht deppots taht tsael ta tuB
.repmihw igroc eht gnikam ,samohT otni kcub a htiw deilper eh ”,nwod lamina na kcol ot dnet od stonk esehT
.thguoht samohT ,draH
”?thgirla gnihtyreve si ,ebab ,edeF“
,desuap dna tnemtrapa eht deretne
.deerga yeht ,noissucsid emos retfA
.weiv otni emac kcoc s’odnamrA fo pit eht erehw ot ,nwod decnalg samohT
,hcterts ot daeh sih dniheb smra
?ebul deen neve yeht diD
gniraew dna ,sessalg eerht htiw yart gnivres a gniyrrac
igroc ot hctorc-flow
.dneterp ton su teL“
,redrah gnitsurht
,apuL aL fo snoitciped rehto ekilnU