”.nam gnikool-doog yrev a saw kcub ehT
,stnemom wef a rof tnelis saw elbas ehT
,elbas eht tih niaga ecno sdrow ehT
,deilper tenaJ ,tnemom a retfA
.erodoehT osla tub
.thgir kcab gniworg reven sreltna sih fo eno sediseb yrevocer lluf a edam eh ,wenk I tsal eht tub
sffucdnah dna dlofdnilb eht ro
won thgir ereh eb neve dluohs eh fi yllatnem detabed erodoehT
siht fo dir eb yllanif ot ytinutroppo siht fo egatnavda ekat dluohs uoy kniht I
,daeh s’elbas eht hguorht detfihs sthguoht eseht sA
.rezalb sih fo edisni eht morf licnep a dna repap fo dap a tuo gnillup ,taes a koot dna
,erofeb elbas a morf nees reven dah yeht taht stnuoma ni
?kcis gnileef t’nerew uoY
,stseretni evol lareves dah erodoehT ,egelloc nI
.msagro t’nac ton ,oN“
,sey ,gnissarrabmE
,dias ,ekops eh sa og ria eht gnittel ylwols dna
.deganam I wohemos tub“
,netsil ot tnaw t’ndid rehtie yeht tub
,deilper erodoehT ,dehgual ylsuovreN
.espalloc llaw eht tlef eh neht dnA
.ytsevart a tahw ,drow yM“
fo lluf si eciffo ym kniht tsum uoY“
.rof depoh dah yeht taht
tohsnug a ekil ybraD .rM hguorht decreip noitalever…sihT
.moordeb eht ot devom ew ,yllautneve tuB
.gnissarrabme rehtar tsuj s’tI“
.em morf yawa reh elots aisenmA
daD regdaB yldduC
,riahc sih ni detfihs elbas eht ,niaga ecnO
.llew sa deksa moor ycnegreme eht ta rotcod eht tahw yltcaxe s’taht ,wonk uoY“
”.tuo nethgiarts lliw efil ym ni esle gnihtyreve ,detfil si esruc siht ecno fi sa leef I
.redaeR ehT dna rotarraN ehT“
,diulf etihw yklim eht was ynneJ dna llewsnarC .rD
.rewsna dluow enoyna fi ees ot tuo llaC
,dias ,delzzup ,elbas ehT
,gnitirw deppots llewsnarC .rD
erofeb deneppah ton sah siht uoy erussa nac I
,enot s’rotcod eht ni tfihs neddus eht yb sucof otni kcab thguorb saw erodoehT
erusaelp fo yenruoj a no ybraD .rM koot yllacidohtem tenaJ dna llewsnarC .rD
;thginot deen uoy sa gnol sa rof lasopsid ruoy ta ma I
,efil sih ni emit tsrif eht rof dnA
.thgin taht fo stneve eht fo kaeps ot flesmih gnirb ot gnilggurts ylraelc ,trihs sih fo ralloc eht ta dellup erodoehT ”.eunitnoc ,esaelP“
:eciov…siht fo esuaceb lla saw
.seitiliba ym ni detsurt uoy esuaceb ereh emac uoY
.lufrewop dna ,wol
”,suolaej ylbidercni erew uoy
s’ybraD erodoehT ni detsevni ylluf won saw llewsnarC .rD
.enoemos s’ti kniht t’nod I
.sesnefed sih tsniaga deyolpme gnieb scitcat fo thgualsno eht tsniaga dloh ot
,nihc sih debbur llewsnarC .rD
,nosib eht detcerroc erodoehT
taht gniyas uoy erA“
.detrofmoc tlef wohemos ybraD .rM
”.sdrawretfa yenom fo hcnub a tuo eb ton dna ’esruc‘
,duol saw eciov ehT
dehsilbup eb noos
.enola yletelpmoc saw eh
,woN ”.gnineve eht rof emoh yaw ym no ydaerla saw I
”.yhw nialpxe t’nac tub
.gnitnuoc dna setunim ruof-ytnewt dna ruoh tsal eht rof
.gnivah era uoy eussi revetahw deciton tsrif uoy nehw em gnillet yb tratS
”.eb ot uoy tnaw ew esuaceb ereh era uoY“
,enoemos ot klat ot dah eh tuB
.”noitpurretni“ txen eht esuac dluow siht dna
”.ecnedicnioc tsuj naht erom saw ti kniht ot detrats I emit tsrif eht saw tahT“
.stcesni eht fo setib eht morf gnilley erodoehT dna haraS gniraeh retfa spoc eht dellac dah ybressap A
.gnineppah ti rebmemer I emit tsrif eht ylno si sihT .latnedicnioc
.ti revo esnepxe sih ta sekoj edam ylevitca ro
.meht nioj ot revo em denokceb ehS“
eno siht piks esaelp
.niaga neppah reve
,wonk uoY .ega fo gnimoc saw I nehw
.noitidnoc eht desuac taht tneve citamuart
”!?siht si tahw ,llewsnarC .rD“ .mih gnikatrevo won rorret
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,rehtegot kcab flesmih llup ot tnemom a koot elbas ehT
yresim dna ,stnemtnioppasid ,niap ,stnedicca ,seirrow
.ylduol deilper nosib egral eht ”!esnesnoN“
”.erusaelp hcus yna evah ton llahs uoy
.deliaf lla evah esoht ,uoy erussa I tub
sthgil tnecseroulf gnimmuh fo ynomrah a dedulcni osla gnos gnibmun-dnim sihT
saw rebmemer I emit tsrif eht esoppus I“
.yoj fo level eht pu depmar ytivitca hcae tub
.rohtuA eht yb dna
,eciffo sih fo rood eht drawot eciov sih gnitcejorp
,deilper erodoehT
.mrof eht dengis ybraD .rM ,pans a htiW .dniw
,deilper ylno ,sliated eht rotcod eht deraps dna htaerb peed a koot erodoehT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
thgilp ruoy fo erawa si redaeR ehT
yas ot retteb eb dluow ti ebyaM
.ffo gniog mrala erif a ni dedne hcihw
eb dluow gnineppah ti rebmemer nac I tseilrae ehT“
dna daeh reh dekcip ehs ,gniwollaws dehsinif ehs retfa dna
,nosib eht ta dekool erodoehT
.noitpurretni eht rof yrroS“ ”.ylbidercnI“
,serusaelp elpmis htiw detrats riap ehT
”?tnesnoc I fi neppah lliw
”.ma I erehw em llet nac uoy…ebyaM“
;eussi ym sa raf sA
.kaeps ot ybraD .rM teg ot gniyrt
stsoh ohw ,remrahc eniuqe eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb
”.msagro na evah t’nac I
.roputs sseldrow a ot ni ybraD .rM decnelis dna
,seciffo ruo evael uoy ecnO
.mih ot gnihtyreve denialpxe ydaerla gnivah annA ,revo emac eh ,lleW“ ”.eunitnoc ,esaelP
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,remrahc
”.deneppah tahw em llet tsuJ“ .dehtoos nosib eht
.efil sih fo mus eht rof dnim sih ni yltnatsnoc gnar taht gniht ylno eht ekops
,derewsna ybraD .rM ,ylsuovreN
,deunitnoc eh erofeb delkcuhc dna deppots elbas ehT
,annA ot deil uoy hguoht neve ,enigami nac I“
,tenaJ dna denepo rood eht ,kcalc duol a htiW ”.deednI“
?neddus saw siht dnA“
,detaeper ybraD .rM
,moor mrod s’erodoehT ni yvaeh dna toh gnitteg erew riap ehT
,gnicitcarp fo sraey neves-ytriht nI
”?gnineve siht seciffo ym otni uoy sgnirb tahw
.did ybraD erodoehT tahw yltcaxe s’taht ,os dnA
.napdaed yletelpmoc ecaf sih
ot ti rof dnetni t’nod I dna
.reganeet a er’uoy nehw si ti woh wonk uoy erus m’I
,demialcxe llewsnarC .rD ”,ybraD .rM ,secnedicnioc fo seires a etiuq s’tahT“
,yltneg delims llewsnarC .rD
lliw uoy msagro suoirolg tsom eht eb lliw ti tub
.llewsnarC .B drofrehtuR .rD ma I“
foohnorI mok’aT yb
.deunitnoc eh erofeb ylduol dehgis dna htaerb peed a ni werd tius nat yratnemelpmoc a ni nosib egral eht ”…woN
.sgnineppah ecnahc fo lufdnah
fo kcas a ekil em deppord esineD si deneppah tahW
.niaga seton gnikat nageb llewsnarC .rD ,deunitnoc erodoehT sA
,hgih erew snoissap :enif gniog saw gnihtyrevE
.deb eht fo egde eht no spih reh ,kcab reh no tog annA .did I…dnA
.gnidliub ylkciuq eelf ot deen a dna ssensuoicsnocbus sih morf tuo yaw rieht gniwalc srotsecna sih fo stcnitsni eht
.flesreh ekil tsuj reeD deR a dekcip evah dluow ehs taht emit eht ta desseug evah dluohs I esoppus I .su rof enoemos dnif ot annA dlot I
.regna tlef elbas eht
,drawrof tnemom taht morf ,os dnA
.”rotarraN ehT“ flesmih dellac ohw eno eht ekil gnieb tnetopinmo na ot
.rotcod ,etaitini ot deirt ehs emit elgnis yreve ,reh ot deil I“
.ybraD .rM ,nosaer dnoyeb ton ma I“
,seye sih desolc llewsnarC .rD
”.mrof erom eno ngis ot uoy deen ot gniog er’ew
”.em thguac rehtom yM“
,eciffo s’llewsnarC .rD ni kcab niaga ecno flesmih dnuof ybraD .rM ,ylnedduS ”?esaelP“
s’tahw…s’tahW“ .esitrepxe s’llewsnarC .rD hguorht gnizilairetam rewsna laitnetop a
.gniunitnoc erofeb emit a rof ylwols gnilahxe dna peed ni gnihtaerb
.gnihtemos ot no deedni saw ybraD .rM fi sa leef ot tub pleh t’ndluoc llewsnarC .rD ,ssol dna evol fo secnatsni erom dna erom htiw mih elager ot deunitnoc erodoehT sA .yrots
taht oga gnol dediced I dna
,tug fo tib riaf a
.rohtuA eht yb dna
!ybraD .rM !ybraD .rM“
,kcolc eht ta derats
.seye sih gnisolc ,drah dewollaws erodoehT ”.deneppah ti nehT
.ybraD .rM ,nwod mlaC“
”,tnemtnioppa na koob ot shtnom em koot ti dna noitan eht ni tsigoloxes gnidael eht er’uoY
,annaoJ saw ecnatsni txen ehT
”.emit eht ta toh saw ti timda ot evah I
.deretne eh sa emarf rood eht tsniaga gnihsurb sredluohs sih ,tius nworb a gniraew dna
,reh dniheb mih htiw devom yeht neht ,pot no saw eh ,tsriF
…23…13…03…92 dna MP 70:6 .dehgis dna
.kcoc s’kcub eht gnikcus detrats annA sa deb eht fo daeh eht ot devom kcub ehT
,ynneJ dna llewsnarC .rD fo ynapmoc eht tfel dah eh nehw erus yleritne t’nsaw ybraD .rM taht
”.drah yrev saw tI
,dneirflrig suoires tsrif yM
”.siht ekil leef uoy yhw nialpxe ot deen ot gniog er’uoy eveileb I“
.secivres ycnegreme dellac ehs ,erodoehT dellik dah ehs gniknihT
.ybraD .rM ,seY“
,yeknod ynnej dalc-xetal eht morf nep eht koot ybraD .rM
,noitabrutsam ta tpmetta txen sih dellacer eH
em sraef ehs ,esrow nevE
ti tuoba klat ot deirt reve ev’I enoyreve
”…ot elba neeb I evah ecno ton dna
,dias ,seton etirw ot nageb dna sessalg sih detsujda nosib ehT
tliub dah eh llaw latnem eht desuac ,enola raef dna ,raef
,secnatsmucric eht neviG
,ria eht ni tfihs a tlef erodoehT
.elkcuhc thgil a tuo tel llewsnarC .rD
.stnemurtsni suoirav fo lluf trac a gnihsup ,ni deklaw
.sehctits deen ot mih gnisuac
yawllah eht morf thgil eht tuo dekcolb etteuohlis gnisopmi na ,emarf eht edisnI
.tiaw gnol eht revo saw erodoehT naht desnecni erom neve saw llewsnarC .rD taht wonk ot gnitrofmoc saw tI
.duola denoitseuq htob ynneJ dna llewsnarC .rD ”?ohw ehT“
tsacdoP s’ynaffiY tA renniD eht
,deilper eh sa eciov s’erodoehT deroloc ssensuovren fo egniwt A ”?ybraD erodoehT“
.dedaf msagro nwo reh retfa deciton ylno ,revewoh ,annaoJ
.mih fo pot no tog ehs neht
.rehto hcae htiw etamitni eb ot detpmetta riap eht retfa yltrohs dedne hcihw fo lla
”.lla ta toh t’nsaw txen deneppah tahw“
”.ylevitcudes ylbidercni os em ta dekool
.llew sa ereh seirots lareves deciov sah dna
,msagro na dah ybraD .rM
,etats latnem nekorb yletelpmoc won sih ni ,ybraD .rM
.hguorht emac tsinoitpecer sih fo eciov eht ,peeb a htiW
”?txen deneppah tahW
.dias llewsnarC .rD
,tuo dekaorc elbas decaf krad eht
,woN ”…fo esuaceb dehcrimseb eb ton lliw eman doog yM .eerf
,niagA ”.esaeler…uoy
.rof nwonk er’uoy gniht eno eht htiw em pleh dluoc uoy gnipoh ereh emac I
,ekops ti drow hcae htiW
,peed dna lufrewop saw eciov eht
.xes gnivah detrats
.meht…esaelp…dluow tI
.tik loot ym em gnirb esaelp ,tenaJ“
rof eciffo eht gnivael nehw od yllamron I sa
a rof niaga gniyrt morf em tpek tnedicni feirb tahT
gnitiaw tneitap a evah I nehw wonk em tel tonnac yeht
raey siht dlo sraey ytroF“
,noisufnoc dezad tsomla na ni riap eht ta gniratS ”.evah reve
”…naem uoy ,hO ?esaeleR“
,draeb gnol a htiw nosib redlo na
”.su fo eerht lla gnirujni ,esuoh ym otni sehsarc rac a
,cipot eht fo thgiew eht gnileef ylsuoivbo
,dezisahpme ybraD .rM ”,uoy erussa I“
.uoy s’ti ,em pleh nac taht enoyna si ereht fi ,yleruS“ .dias erodoehT
.taes wor-tnorf a dah I
.daeh reh ni sehctits emos dedeen ehs kniht I
,llet t’ndluoc eH
”.trats neve ot erehw wonk t’nod…I“
,uoy ot sknaht lla
,yltneitap os reve gnitiaw
,deilper ,taeb a gnissim ton ,nosib redlo ehT
,deunitnoc erodoehT
.taoc onibaS a htiw esroh gniklaw yab a
,derewsna ,roolf eht ta nwod gnikool won ,erodoehT ”!?TAHW“
.eb dluow ti enigami nac I“
”.yletairporppa sserd esaelP
”sddO ehT erA tahW“   yojne esaelP
”.trats ot ecalp doog a syawla s’tahT
”,yawa dessap ehs em llet t’nod esaelP“ ”…revewoh ,annA
,riahc sih ni detfihs nosib ehT ”.emit gnol
?nettogrof eb eh dluoc woH
elbas eht ot dellac llewsnarC .rD
.tsen s’tna na fo pot no thgir detalupoc dah yeht taht deciton dah erodoehT ron haraS rehtieN
.evloser sih rehtag ot detpmetta elbas roop eht sa tnelis deniamer
m’I ekil mees t’nseod ti ,naem I
.nam a rof esucxe dlo-raey-ytrof siht morf gnimoc levird eht ot netsil dluow rotcod eht fi ro
,sboj suoirav dekrow ,flesym ot tpek tsuj I
,aionarap sa thgilp sih dessimsid
.retnec sti ta ekal eht raen syawhtap s’krap eht fo ffo gniraelc elttil a dnuof dna dekan nettog dah srevol owt ehT
eht retfa diarfa gnimoceb tub aisenma gnivah eno devol a
”sddO ehT erA tahW“
tneitap ym era uoy ,ybraD .rM“
rotarraN ehT ma I tuB
sdrawretfa latipsoh eht ni erodoehT tisiv neve t’ndid ehs ,dezitamuart os saw annaoJ
.elbissop enigami dluoc eno taht enoz suonegore yreve dna ,selppin ,suna ,slatineg sih gnirusaelp secived elpitlum ,elbat eht ot depparts llits
,ffo krej ot detpmetta ev’I semit eht lla htiw sruoh rof no og dluoc I“ ”.eunitnoc ,esaelP
,depmarc gel sih ,dehcaorppa msagro sih sa tub
,ereh yaw ruoy dnuof ev’uoy taht woN
,no gnimoc msagro ym leef ot detrats I sa tsuJ“
.snosaes gnitam eht dnuora yllaicepsE
.feilebsid ni daeh sih koohs llewsnarC .rD ,kcohs ni llitS
ehT…dna…rotarraN ehT…tem…I…I“
,nekorb saw sivlep s’erodoehT ,ecneuqesnoc yb
,eelf ot dna kaeps ot htob
,’lortnoc tsol‘ dias I nehW
.degnahc gnihtemos ,yllanif ,nehT
.gnihsilbuP sirneF yb
.ereh llits er’uoy taht tluaf ym yletelpmoc si ti ,ybraD .rM“
.tnemtnioppa siht edam neve evah t’ndluohs eh snosaer fo elip eht fo pot no worht ot nosaer erom eno saw tiaw sihT
.yadot ereh emoc ot eciohc eht edam ev’uoy taht dalg yrev os m’I ,ybraD .rM“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.sseug I ,neppah sgnihT .thgirla s’taht…hO“
.drow yreve draeh tsinoitpecer sih taht erus gnikam yltnerappa
.ybraD .rM ,ecnerrucco nommoc ylriaf a s’tahT“
.sevren sih retslob ot dnah sih gnignirw won
.tnemtnioppa siht ekam neve ot evren eht pu dekrow evah ot mih rof hguone drah saw tI
ylneddus wenk ybraD .rM tub
.noitisop tfihs ot erodoehT gnisuac
eerf si noisses eritne
”?ffo siht tes evah dluoc taht gnihtyna tae uoy diD
ni uoy pleh ll’I taht esimorp osla I
?sddo eht era tahW
,eganam dluoc eh sa ediw sa erew seye s’elbas ehT
.seigolopa ruoy tnaw t’nod I ,llewsnarC .rD esaelP“ ”.ybraD
,deunitnoc llewsnarC .rD dna
,siht rof tub ,smrof tnesnoc lareneg ruo dengis ydaerla ev’uoy wonk I
.delzzup eb ot nrut s’llewsnarC .rD saw ti woN
.eciffo ym ot rotisiv emit-tsrif a dna
.ega fo gnimoc tsrif saw I nehw
”!em tsniaga gniripsnoc si esrevinu eht ekil s’tI
”.tib a tsuj t’nsaw ti
,seuqinhcet ruo lla esu ot su wolla uoy fi ,ybraD .rM“
.llac eht dne ot emit tsal a nottub eht gnisserp
,deilper erodoehT ,ylhsipeehS
,yas ot deganam
”?gniddew nwo ruoy gnitammusnoc fo diarfa eb ot si ti drah woh wonk uoy oD“
.xof a fo nexiv der a ,eilrahC saw ereht ,tsriF
,sgel s’ybraD .rM neewteb nwod gnikooL
,efil ym ni emit tsrif eht rof etalucaje dna egairram ym etammusnoc yllanif ot tuoba saw I sa tsuJ
,detcejretni llewsnarC .rD ”…ew sa ecaf reh rebmemer llits I .llirht etulosba na saw ti dna
,koohs sllaw eht ,hceeps sih fo trap tsal eht htiW ”!ECIFFO YM ni
,detuohs llewsnarC .rD
,ffo enohp ym denrut t’ndah I ,ecnatsneppah yB
.retsum dluoc luos latrom yna fo sgninigami eht dnoyeb eno
a rof nommocnu ton tub
,msagro na evah uoy lliw ylno ton taht eetnaraug I
.sseldne eb ot demees kcub taht fo animats eht elihw demsagro annA ,niaga revo dna revO
.sraey 02 tsomlA
.detpurretni llewsnarC .rD
.elkcuhc a tuo gnitrons erofeb desuap llewsnarC .rD ”.nac I taht yaw rehto yna
.yadot tnemtnioppa etal a dah I em gnillet rehtob t’ndid tsinoitpecer yM
,enihcam odlid dna srotabrutsam noitcus-otua fo riap eht ro
eniuqe eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb ”sddO ehT erA tahW“ saw sihT      .redaeR ehT
eht ot noituac werht dna ,hgis gnol a tuo dehtaerb
,dna pot no eb ot dednamed eram egral eht
.edistuo ciffart fo dnuos tniaf eht yb dedivorp ydolem lanoitidda na yb detautcnup rehtruf
.dnatsrednu etiuq t’nod I ,yrros m’I“
.nalp yksir a hcus otni reh gniklat rof erodoehT demalb haraS ,devirra ecilop eht retfA
sniap ylraelc tI
,mih deracs ti hguohT
.noitseuq a otni demrof ecaf s’erodoehT
,deilper erodoehT ”,did tsomla tI“ ”!dam
.egassem txet a aiv mih htiw pu ekorb dna
,gnivah er’uoy eussi eht em llet ,tsriF
,dnah a desiar erodoehT ”…tub ,uoy
si ereht fI .tsigoloxes a ma I ,ybraD .rM“
.stiolpxe lauxes sih tuoba llewsnarC .rD dlot rehtruf erodoehT ,erofeb sA
”.meht ecneirepxe ew litnu sknik ruo wonk ton od ew ,semitemoS“
”.yllautneve ti od lla eW .deednI“
.uoy ot pu ti ekam si od nac ew tsael ehT
,llew sa sehtolc ym ffo deppirts I ,yllautnevE
,dias ,gel rehto eht fo pot eht revo fooh eno gnissorc
.riahc sih ni pmuj ot llewsnarC .rD gnisuac ylbisiv dna riahc eht no nwod stsif sih gnimmals
”…thgin eno etal tol gnikrap dedulces a dnuof ew ,od ot enorp era stluda gnuoy sa
.gnikcarc eciov sih
.dah I segru lauxes yna gnisserppus htiw deifsitas eb tsuj ot lleh ekil deirt dna
.elbissop yaw hcihw yreve dekcuf teg efiw ym dehctaw I sa renroc eht ni flesym gnikorts
.esuoh ruo otni thgiarts dna daor eht ffo deneerac rac A .thgir s’tahT“
.ti rof degduj eb ton dna melborp sih tuoba enoemos llet yllanif ot ytinutroppo ylno sih eb thgim siht ,revewoH
secnatsmucric fo tes ddo ylbidercni na tahW“
.tsap eht ni dah I enutrofsim eht lla saw tnemom taht ta dnim ym no gniht tsal ehT
.demrahnu yltsom saw ehs ,yllacisyhp ,oN
ot dewolla
”,won thgir era uoy ekil tsuj detcaer sah
,htaerb peed a ni koot
.krap cilbup a ni rehtegot etamitni eb ot gnitpmetta erew riap eht nehw dedne
.rM ,yrros ylbidercni os m’I
”,nedrub a eb ot tnaw t’nod I .enif s’ti ,yllaeR“
s’thginoT .ybraD .rM ,uoy dnimer em teL“ ”.wonk t’nod I“
.edisa erusaelpsid sih tas erodoehT
,ylgnihtoos tuo detnurg nosib eht ”,seY“ ”?gninnigeb ehT“
,msagro gninaw won eht htiw seslup ni diulf lanimes kael ot deunitnoc ydob sih sa htaerb sih hctac ot gnilggurts llits ,elbas ehT
.erodoehT drawot drawrof gninael dna pu gnittis won
”.llaw moordeb ruo hguorht tsrub rac a
,daeh reh rof tpecxe tius xetal lluf a ni desserd won
uoy evird ot hguone neeb evah tsum tI
”.ereht morf krow lliw eW
?sciryl tuohtiw etelpmoc eb t’ndluow gnos tahw dnA
stiwtin lanoisseforpnu
,deilper llewsnarC .rD ”,gniwollof ton llits m’I“ ”.msagro
,ylimaf dna sdneirf sih htiw seussi sih pu gnirb ot detpmetta dah eh ,efil sih tuohguorhT .enoyna
.rood ym ot uoy dael taht
,moor gnitiaw eht ni emit sih sediseB
.dah ehs fi retteb neeb evah dluow ti ,syaw emos nI“
.xes gnivah nageb kcub eht dna annA“
,kcuc a gnieb tuoba annA ot gniyl saw I hguoht nevE
.neeb dah eh erehw regnol on saw eh taht
.diov eht morf detaname eciov gnilbmur ,peed a dna
lliw ’ecnatsiD ehT gnioG‘ ,yrots siH
.nageb yeht elihw ’hctaw‘ dluoc I os renroc eht ni riahc a tup dah eW
.esuap rof nosaer a uoy nevig evah thgim reilrae morf stneve
,tsael tA .enoemos…toN“
”!efiw ym htiw gnitam htiw demusnoc ylluf saw dnim yM
,taefed reehs ni tsomlA
,gnineve siht evael uoy erofeb ,uoy esimorp I
,niaga tub deugirtni etiuq m’I ,ybraD .rM“
.esaeler…uoy wolla ot em rof sehsiw dna
htuom s’annA otni daol sih detsub eh sa wolleb kcub reeD deR eht draeh I
.mih ot kcab ohce neve t’ndid eciov siH ”?olleH“
s’erodoehT .eilrahC htiw pihsnoitaler sih fo dne eht saw sihT
.ylfeirb desuap erodoehT ,niagA ”.did I oS“
,lleW“ .gniylper erofeb pal sih otni nep dna repap sih gnittis
,noitercsidni s’gnineve siht fo esuaceB
.degnahc dah epacsdnal eht fi ees ot semit lareves dnuora gnikool
a sediseb no og ot hcum em nevig ton ev’uoy raf os
,deilper nosib eht ”,tenaJ ,uoy knahT“
,enips s’erodoehT pu tperc ylfeirb raeF
.erodoehT derewsna
.gnineve siht reilrae ekatsim ruo fo esuaceb
,riahc sih otni kcab dexaler llewsnarC .rD ,elkcuhc thgil a htiW
.ylduol dehgis erodoehT ,niagA
.ffo llewsnarC .rD eht gnittuc
.annA gnikcuf detrats dna reh ot pu deklaw I“
.eye driht sih hguorht detloj tniop siht ot pu hguorht neeb dah eh gnihtyreve fo seiromem ehT
,uoy erussa I dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.owt ro tnemom a em eviG .llewsnarC .rD ,yaw ym no m’I“
;sdnuos ti woh wonk I“
stniartser sih morf ybraD .rM gnisaeler tuoba tnew ynneJ
.derewsna erodoehT ,noitangiser fo hgis a tuo gnitteL
,dna tniop siht ta shtnom wef a rof gnitad neeb d’eW
.hctarcs a dereffus ylerab I ,ees uoy sa dnA
”.ti rof dnats t’now I dna
.tuo dellac yeknod yarg eht fo eciov gnos-gnis ehT ”?llewsnarC .rD ,seY“
.deerga llewsnarC .rD
.trihs pu-nottub deveels-gnol eulb sih fo sffuc eht fo snottub eht htiw gnitegdif daetsni
.efil ym ni erofeb xes dah reven d’I ekil reh dekcuF
”…annA ,efiw etal ym tem I nehw s’tahT
,wodniw yrots-dnoces eht fo tuo llef neht erodoehT ,ecnalab sih gnisoL
.ronaemed mlac a htiw gnikaeps won nosib egral eht
.elbissop enigami ot nugeb neve evah wef taht
.dnah sih fo stigid suonitarek eht hguorht gnissap draeb sih fo sdnarts gnol eht
?wonk uoy ,ecno ti deirt eW“
.snoitseuq ruoy fo lla ot ’on‘ si rewsna eht dna em htiw gnorw gnihtyna dnif t’ndluoc yehT .ssergid I“
eht fi ezigolopa I“
”,ylsuoires em ekat dluow enoemos hsiw I ,ecno tsuJ“
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.flesym gnirolpxe tsrif saw I nehw
.secnedicnioc ;si ti lla llits si taht tub“
”.trohs siht ekam d’uoy dias uoy ,ybraD .rM“
…kcot…kcit…kcot…kcit…kcot…kciT
nehw…neppah ot tuoba tsuj msagro ym leef dluoc I dna
.ecneserp ruoy fo gniwonk erofeb emoh tsomla saw I !thginot nevE
erodoehT fo tnorf ni elbat eht dnuora deklaw llewsnarC .rD
.mih desserp llewsnarC .rD tub
.erofeb draeh neeb reve dah taht gnihtyna ekilnu erusaelp fo naom a tuo tel eH
.stniartser sih tsniaga ylithgim dellup sgel dna smra siH
.desuap niaga ecno erodoehT
,gniylper erofeb ylitraeh dehgual nosib redlo ehT
,relooc retaw gnilbbub dna
.emit gnol yrev a rof elgnis deniamer I ,stiolpxe egelloc ym retfA“
,delkcuhc erodoehT
,sevren fo eldnub suoixna reve eht ,erodoehT
daD regdaB yldduC ,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
.oga sraey ruof dnuora litnu ,si tahT
,ehtaerb ylno dluoc ybraD .rM tub
tahW“ .yletelpmoc noisserpxe sih deroloc ylniatrecnu dna raef
”?msagro t’nac uoy ,naem uoy od tahW
.kcohs morf tuo ssap ot nam roop eht gnisuac
”.eerf em tes yehT
dna dlokcuc a saw I decnivnoc reh dah neve I
.suoivbo llits saw terger sih tub
,tnatsissa ym si tenaJ .em si ti
”,dnuora gninrut yllanif si kcul ym fi sa mees dluow tI“ ”.yad eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
dnuof ybraD .rM ,epacsdnal etihw yletelpmoc ,wen sih nI ?spahrep ,maerd A .esle erehwemos yletinifed saw eh tub
.reh ot kcab seiromem reh gnirb ot deirt
.niaga sffuc sih htiw gnitegdif dna nwod gnikool erofeb dias erodoehT
.gel sih kaerb ot mih gnisuac
,raeB nuS lufituaeb a
moor eht otni rehtruf deppets erugif gnisopmi eht ,ylkciuq sa tsuJ
etihw tnew noisiv yM“
,seiromem sih llacer ot gnitnaw ton ylraelc
,seton gnitirw deppots llewsnarC .rD
.taes lyniv ykaeuqs eht no yltneitapmi detfihs eh sa riahc eht fo dnuos eht dna shgis suoirav htiw flesmih eseht dedivorp erodoehT ,ylikcuL
”.yaw rieht evah dluohs redaeR ehT yhw nosaer a em evig
.ma I sa delliks sa tsomla si ehs
,deksa ,pu gnikool
.xelpmoc eciffo eritne eht ot hguorht gnitanoser sdrow eht
”?deneppah tahW .su ot klat ot uoy deen ew
.ti rof sehsiw redaeR ehT
”?era uoy ohw em llet uoy nac ,llew ,seY“
annA fo noitnem eht ta tnelis tnew erodoehT
,kaeps ot tnemom a koot elbas ehT
”.elpoep rehto htiw xes evah reh hctaw rehtar dluow
,seirujni suoires lareves deniatsus eh ,yug rehto eht rof sA“
.yot xes eht tsniaga dleifelttab eht no natrapS a ekil thguof dna dexelf etatsorp siH
kcolc eciffo ledom dradnats demmir kcalb eht fo skcilc tnatsnoc ehT
”!gniyrt fo kcal a rof toN
,msagro ot uoy gnirb nac ohw enoyna
esnecni enomorehp dna ™ysatscE fo serutxim eht saw ti fi erus t’nsaw ybraD .rM
,riahc sih ni ylbatrofmocnu detfihs erodoehT ,niagA
.ecaf sih nopu kool lacizziuq a htiw llits ,denediw seye s’llewsnarC .rD
”.wollef rehto eht dna annA ot deneppah tahw em lleT
.ybraD .rM ,tey toN“
”.em rof tuo lla ti yal ,ybraD .rM
.taht ekil gnihtemos ro niveK ro dahC .won eman sih rebmemer neve t’nod I
”.’efiw etal‘ ruoy saw ehs dias uoY“
.gninnigeb eht ta trats ,neht
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
dna od stluda sa did ew ,trohs yrots gnol a ekam oT“
.llew sa ereht gnittis mocretni llams eht no nottub a gnisserp erofeb riahc sih ot txen elbat llams eht no dapeton dna nep sih decalp eH
,dessap sah taht ecnis won ,lleW“
,msagro ot tuoba saw eh tlef ybraD .rM nehw semit lareves erew ereht hguoht ,revewoH
,haraS ,tseretni evol txen
.pal sih otni rehtegot sdnah sih gnignirb
.em ton ,lleW .haeY“
,reduol neve ekops llewsnarC .rD
.dneirf a htiw gnineve doog a dah tsuj ,yltsenoh ,dna ,semag emos deyalp ,rennid dah eW
,ediw tnew seye s’erodoehT
.deilper erodoehT
dedaehria os s’ohw ysoolf emos…“
.yltneloiv gnivaeh saw tsehc sih
,llewsnarC .rD dna
”?thgirla uoy erA
.spil s’ybraD .rM tfel dah sdrow eht sa noos sa dednopser yltnatsni tsomla eciov ehT
”?neppah ot gniog
,sdrow esoht detuohs erodoehT
.rovref a otni dnim sih gnikcohs
.kcoc sih morf htrof gnirps noitartsurf lauxes pu tnep fo htrow s’emitefil a fo lavaehpu eht tlef eh dna desnet ydob siH
,esaelp ,ybraD .rM“
.tnedive noitartsurf sih ,dehgis erodoehT
,em eveileB .sdnuos siht yzarc woh wonk I ,llewsnarC .rD“
,desaelp eh sa og dna muc ot eerf saw ybraD .rM
.llew sa secivres ruoy fo deen ni eb yam I ,oslA
,ereh gnittis neeb won dah eh
ev’yeht ,sraey lareves tsal eht roF
:ylluf detanimulli won saw dna
.flesmih ot thguoht eh
”.niaga emas eht em ees reven dluoc ehs dias ehs tub ,elicnocer ot deirt eW .seotatop
”.slewob ym fo lortnoc tsol I
”,tsol tib a m’I ,iH .sey ,mU“
.yltnatcepxe ,gnitiaw
”.sevlesmeht tuoba gninrael dlihc rieht no ni klaw yllatnedicca ot tnerap
,etam ot detpmetta riap eht sA
”,ybraD .rM ,nwod mlaC“
.etar ylruoh lluf ruo uoy egrahc ot evah lliw ew
.niaga kaeps ot ecnedifnoc eht dnuof eh ,nehT .ton dah tI
ekorb ni gnittis saw eh riahc eht nehw detrawht saw tpmetta txen siH
.detarbiv ydob elohw sih
”.redaeR
.stna saw ti ,emit sihT
.tiaw gnol eht rof yrros ylbidercni m’I“
,denrut bonkrood eht sa yltpurba detpurretni erew sthguoht siH
.mih derewsna eciov eht ,revewoH
,tas llewsnarC .rD sa edulretni na nageb tiaw s’erodoehT fo ynohpmys ehT
htiw devlovni yllacitnamor neeb dah erodoehT taht rentrap tsegral eht saw siht ,etad oT
.sdrow sih no delbmuts eh
,deilper ,ylthgil dehgual nosib ehT ”.reganeet
.rentrap a htiw tpmetta na ekam dluoc eh litnu noitacifitarg-fles ta seruliaf dna stpmetta lareves yb dewollof saw sihT
,ekops eh sa pu deraet erodoehT
,sruoh elbarusaemmi fo tes gniwollof eht revO
,sdrow s’llewsnarC .rD gniredisnoC
.ybraD .rM fo sdrow eht deredisnoc llewsnarC .rD ,niagA
llewsnarC .rD rof citrahtac ylno ton yltnerappa saw regna fo noisolpxe sihT
”?uoy gnitneverp si enoemos
.msagro na evah lliw uoy
:fo kniht dluoc eh taht gniht lacigol ylno eht did ybraD .rM os
.dam erodoehT evird ot hguone tsomla erew
,gnitterf eht llA
:erofeb gnineppah taht fo draeh ylniatrec ev’I“
,uoy llet nac I tuB
.daeh sih ni latot gninnur a tpek dah
.ylkciuq gninepo rood eht
.srae s’ybraD .rM ni lufniap gnieb fo tniop eht ot tsomla
dna onrop a gnihctaw ekil saw tI
.worbeye desiar a htiw erodoehT ta pu gnikool
.spih reh no sdnah reh decalp ehs sa kaeuqs wols a tuo tel detrops won ehs tius xetal knip toh ehT .llewsnarC .rD ediseb pu deklaw tenaJ
”.em gnitsurt eunitnoc ot uoy deen I
,mih ta gniraet erew sevren sih dna dehcrap tlef taorht s’erodoehT hguohtlA
”!ti enod ev’eW .kciuq emoc ,ynneJ“
snoissimbuS   .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ksed a otni daeh sih demmals erodoehT dna
”.em s’taht…s’taht ,seY“
.rotarraN ehT
,ruos denrut ecaf sih dna desuap erodoehT ”…nialCcM esineD
”.ybraD .rM ,olleH“
gnicnivnoc eb dluoc ro dluow ti ekil demees tnemom eht ta fo kniht dluoc eh gnihton ,revewoH
?trats eussi ruoy did nehW .gninnigeb eht“