.syug evitcartta erom raf yldettimda rof neve erofeb
.niaga tuo dehtaerb I
krow ta duts uobirac taht
etomer a no derevocsid I eloH eulB eht edulcni ot gniog er'yeht tub ,skcerw fo lufdnah a ,sfeer yltsom si gniviD
- lla retfa naebbiraC eht saw tI
,rewohs eht ni deppets I nehw taht neht ti saw yhW  ".haeY"
,sehtolc emos no werht I
dedracsid siH  .yawa raf oot saw erusaelp ym naht rehto gnihtyna fo thguoht taht niarb ym fo trap eht dna
.hcuot ni tpek ohw inu
,issaveleT yb ”eloH eulB
nibac ynit ruo ni keew siht stnemom eht lla hguorht deyalp I
.gnivid tuo yrt ot tog ohw eno eht saw ekeZ
denilcni yaw siht tlef reven d'I
.gniliec nedoow eht fo snrettap gnilriws eht ni tnadifnoc a gnidnif
***  .rood dekcolnu eht otni delbmuts I sa
dehsup thguoht a
.senigne eht fo muh eht yb derewoprevo
,eloh eulb a gnivid fo ytilibissop eht tuoba
.pahsim a tsuj s'tI"
- tuons ym fo pit kcalb gnireviuq eht delkcit
.llifer a uoy tog I ,dloc gniog s'eeffoC"
.naeco eht evas ot gnihsiw yksuh yknal a dna aneyh ynwarcs a
ruo ni erom gnihtemos fo tnih yna nwohs ro
,yleniuneg dehgual emit siht dna daeh ym koohs I
.ediw daerps pmur pmulP
saw elohtrop nepo eht hguorht naeco eht fo pal eltneg lausu ehT
.lausu naht dehctip rehgih tib a tuo emac tI
.elohliat lufituaeb sih tuoba ysatnaf dirul hcae ot rednerrus ot
,daeh ym fo tuo dehsup erew ytsedom tnerappa sih revo snrecnoc tuB .derevocsid d'eh
- liat dna - ydob sih gnitsiwt ,dehsulb ekeZ
,htap ruo dnoyeb tuo nrut dna tsiwt dluow feer laroc a fo dnab eruza eht ,yllanoisaccO
.ytingid sih evreserp dna
?tnereffid yna eb ekeZ dluohs yhw os
,gnihton was tub moor eht dennacs I ?dedracsid
.ria eht gnical stnerruc elbisivni eht enivid thgim I os ylduol gniffins
,kced dereuqcal eht no gnihctarcs swalc
.sthgiled enitsirp llits ,wef suoicerp sti ni gnirahs
,htnom a ffo yad a tog ylerar eh hguoht neve dnA
gnihcraes tpek I tub
...tuo thgin dliw ylralucitrap a retfa taht ekil pu nekow d'eh spahreP
devil s’eh efil eht htiw noitcartta dnuof-wen sih elicnocer
"!etal siht ton yllausu er'uoY"
.gniliec eht ot pu kcab dellor seye sih elihw kcen sih fo kcab eht gnihctarcs ,ylhsipeehs deggurhs
.tnecs sih htiw tonk ym depparw dna raewrednu sih
,gnineppah saw tahw dessecorp
.flesym erussaer ot gniyrt ,desuap I ",nibac llams a
",taht eveileb nac I"
t'ndid eh tub ,esnopser ni dehctiwt srae s'ekeZ
.reffo dluoc gniknird tsrow eht saw oottat a rof ruf ruoy gnihcaelb taht gnikniht saw I ereh dnA
.ecnetsixe cidamon sih htiw dengila dah srats yM
1 traP ,issaveleT yb
s'ekeZ "!ekawa erew uoy kniht t'ndid I"  .esruoc fo
".oot kciuq gniog s'tsafkaerB"
.looc sgniht peek ot devres
- ycrem llams taht fo dalg tsuj saw I
,raewrednu eht fo
.ytisnetni ni delbuod gnileef yddig eht dna
.dees ym mih evig ot deen eht htiw yletarepsed denruhc sllab ym ekil tlef tI
.htaehs ym ni elgnit siht llits saw ereht ,gniliec etihw knalb eht ta pu derats tsuj I nehw nevE
htob ew erofeb sdnoces fo elpuoc lluf a saw tI
.toh neht ,retaw dloc
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.saw yltcaxe siht tahw wonk t'ndid I
.llits erom evarc em edam taht ria eht ni gnihtemos saw
,mih fo gnileef eht ni dethgiled sesnes ym elihW
,elgnit ydob ym edam borht hcaE
ta tuo deppord ekeZ
pmur sih fo sruotnoc trep ,ylepahs eht dna
,thgiled fo sevaw htiw sevren ym gnihsaw
.thgiled lanimilbus a ekil seye ym erofeb gnihsalf
,erongi ot elbayojne oot raf tonk ym fo ezeeuqs yreve edam
.eerf gnidils kcoc ym fo hcni
.neeb reve dah ti tlef ti naht redrah saw tonk ym
.edis s'ekeZ gnirevoc tevud delpmurc eht no deregnil seye yM
?yas I dluoc esle tahW
,tnegnup eht edisni dehctiwt tonk evitisnes ym sa neve
.rettam yllaer t'ndid tI
.htaerb ym dleh I sa gnirekcilf
,relevart wollef ruoy
llits tey ,tlas fo gnat eht htiw yksum elttil a ,enilucsam ,peed
,deb ym tsniaga dehcuorc I sa
,yawgnag s'draobaevil eht pu
rehtaef elbisivni na fi sa
.tsaot dna sgge delbmarcs fo etalp a htiw gnola
;syad boj-ksed yerg ym ot eruza laciport fo sedahs dedda sthgiled citauqa fo rennam lla fo serutciP
?em draeh eh daH
,dnim ym no detnirpmi saw taht weiv eht tuB
"!edud yrros ,tihs hA"
gnireviuq esaerc dna elknirw eltbus hcae ,ylhtooms dehcnelc
.ecnereffidni lennahc ot gnipoh ,derettum I
,revo saw ti thguoht I emit hcae
,gniog tpek I .wap dehcnelc ym
.retteb neve dellems ew rehtegot - aneyh dna yksuH
.liated eht no detsaef seye ym ,sevren nettogrof ,dlo emos nwod gnirif
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,wap ym ni erew stnaprednu
.seitnewt ylrae ruo ecnis mih nwonk d'I
.em hguorht gnidoolf feiler ykahs ,delims dna htaerb peed ,gnol a koot I
.yellag eht ni pu detsop saw eciton ehT"
.flesmih revoc dluoc eh fi sa
"!enigne eht revo uoy raeh t'ndid I"
,wols htiw devom eh
.deb ym rednu delpmurc
.tsafkaerb erofeb evid tsrif eht rof ekeZ gninioj erofeb xif eeffoc a nwod plug dna rewohs eht hguorht pmuj
.lluh eht tsniaga demmarc deb ym
,yad eht fo dne eht ta tub
.gnivid htiw od ot gnihtyna t'nsaw ,seye ym desolc I revenehw em gnitnah
,gnisitonpyh saw thgis ehT
.yzah saw yromem ym tub
.ti noitseuq t'ndid aneyh eht tub ,deffins ekeZ  .deil I
.enim fo dnasuoht a htrow llits erew yeht
.liatkcoc tnetop a otni
.wol siht nrub gniredluoms a fo erom gnimoceb elgnit eht gnidnif
.lained rof sdrow ycnaf htiw meht revo etorw dna
- tnecs sih fo htaerb tnetop ,lluf a tog I  .kcuF
tsrow eht kced woleb esoht eraps dna ,htaeneb etalucric dluoc ezeerb aes hserf eht taht os tliub neeb gnivah pihs eht -
.gnorts saw tnecs sih ,doof eht dna ,eeffoc eht ,rewohs sih etipseD
,dias dah aneyh eht gnihtemos derebmemer I  ?yllaeR
.nwad ta evila semoc feer eht sa retaw eht otni gnippils neht dna
ereht dna eeffoc barg ot gniog tuoba gnihtemos delbmum I kniht I
eulb thgil a otni moor eht gnignulp dna
reffo na em evag aneyh eht ,yadhtrib hteitriht ym erofeb esolc ,yad eno nehT
.skeew owT .naebbiraC
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf seigolohtna psarG ruO nihtiW snevaeH ehT gnimocpu eht dna
.rebme gniwolg a tlef I ,sehsa eht ni deiruB
rebmemer I .ygoloib eniram
citsilaernu ton tub ,ebyam elbadiovA
”eloH eulB s’ekeZ“   yojne esaelP
ni dnif nac uoy krow esohw
.noitapicitna lausnes htiw
;keew tsrif ruo ni smaerd dna sreeb gnippaws
,htaehs pmulp sih fo weiv no edis a evag ylno eh daetsnI
yltnecer erom ro
deb ym fo emarf eht tsniaga kcab denael I
,yawa deppis I sa wodniw eht tuo dekool I
neey ehT ".yadiloh eht niur ti tel t'noD .reilrae tuobA"
eht yB .ruoh artxe na rof deb ni yawa derons I elihw
.elbat eht otno nwod gnidduht swap ,deppiuq ekeZ "!remaerdyad ayeH"
,detalid yromem eht ydaerla tub
,elzzum sih ni deffuts rotaluger yknuhc
.retteb yna eraf t'ndid I tub
.ti detnaw tsomla I fi sa sdnoces otni tuo gnihcterts
.htuom gniretaw ym tuoba thguoht I
.gnorw tnemaciderp tnerruc ym devorp taht selpmaxe rof
"?taht raeh t'ndid I ?yhW"
ot deirt I ,ezah eht hguorht gnihsuP  .derevocsid d'I
"?taht seod ecalp fo dnik
.spil ym gninesool lla ti morf tloj eht
,secalp ni sselhtaerb dednuos
gnileef ,repap gnihsup
.gninrom siht ylrae deneppah tI  2 fo
dna dekaeuqs ti os decrof elttil a ,dehgual dna daeh ym koohs I
;trofmoc t'nsi draobaevil evid a fo aedi elohw eht ,llitS
yteixna dna sevren htiw dedlem tnemeticxE
",emit txen rood eht kcol
.su neewteb ecnelis eht ni gnireviuq eloh eulb siH
s’ekeZ““ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     .delbmum I
,segassem neewteb shtnom saw ti semitemoS
- xof ehtil taht saw ereht ytisrevinu tA
.toh llits erew sgninrom eht ,remmus ni neve
,tcaf taht fo suoicsnoc
,ylgnisirprusnu ,peelS  .euh
...tub ,wen gnihtemoS
.enituor eht htiw railimaf os t'nsaw I ekeZ ekilnu dna
.eeffoc fo pis gnitrofmoc a koot I
.reilrae pu nekow dah aneyh eht demussa I
".siht ekil ecaps llams a ni emitemos neppah ot dnuoB"
,denekciuq traeh yM  .ti ffuH
.sretupmoc evid ruo morf noitamrofni eht htiw skoobgol ruo etadpu dna sevid s'yadretsey tuoba klat llams ekam ot no tnew eW
.dnoyeb rodirroc krad ,gnol eht gninnacs
.oot tuo deppord d'I hsiw I
.sruoh fo elpuoc txen eht revo od ot tahw fo noitseuq eht evlos ot gnipoh ,decnuonna I
wen a ,htaehs ym ot eslup wen a thguorb mih fo htaerb hcaE
,amora larutan sih ni regnil ti eciton tub pleh t'ndluoc I ,ti
ylpmis dluoc I ,ekow I emit
"!evid gniwolb-dnim a eb ot gniog si eloH eulB sihT .ereht uoy ees
edis ym ot retaw fo sertil fo sdnasuoht ,naf yarts a rof moor on saw ereht fi nevE
.noitcaer ym ssecorp
- tuoba ssuf a ekam t'nod uoy tub
.hsidurp gnieb tsuj er'uoY
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,tnecs etamitni sih dessecorp eson ym elihW
".yadot sevid owt tsrif eht dellecnac yehT
tsuj saw eugnot sih taht ddo em kcurts tI
,erongi ot elbissopmi ti edam liat ynwarcs ,detfil siH
.edisni retaw gninnur fo dnuos on saw ereht
.dedeecer ylbativeni evaw lanif eht litnu
ruogiv dewener htiw em revo gnillor tpek msagro ym - strups ym fo tnuoc tsol I
.eloH eulB s'ekeZ ot delias ew elihw
s'ekeZ“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
neppah ot gniog s'taht sgniht esoht fo eno tsuj s'tI"
.deddon ekeZ ",dooG"
esor nus eht sa kcabrepap dnah-dnoces
.gninrom siht ni tpels I"
.rood eht gnittuhs naht rehtar swap ym htiw seye ym gnidleihs ,depley I
.edit eht lortnoc t'ndluoc I tub ,elbissop sa gnol sa rof gnigde tpek I
.flesym tuoba wenk I thguoht I gnihtyreve kcipnu ot tnaw t'ndid I .egnahc ot tnaw t'ndid I
,werg naeco eht fo llews eht ,no tnew emit sA
,ecnadnuba gniworg
,mih ot yllarutan emac tsuj gniviD
?taob siht no tops a uoy evas eh did yhw nehT
,ti denepo dah I sa yltfiws sa tsuj em dniheb rood eht desolc I
.deb ym otno sehtolc ym dessot dna ,ruf ym ot nwod deppirts ylkciuq I
.sgnul ym gniytpme ,deffuh I ",siht tuohtiw od
.reffo dluoc stnecs elats fo syad
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,inu ta detnemirepxe reven d'eW
- ytisrevinu emas eht ta tcejbus emas eht deiduts eW
,tuo detrulb I
.enif tuo emac sdrow eht emit sihT
nac yksuh eht ,fi dnim reven ,woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
ebyaM .detcepxenu gnihton dnuof dna
,llaw eht dna sserttam ym neewteb koon eht ni flesym degdew I
,feer eht no enola gnieb
".em rof ton s'eh tuB"
.htaerb tsal yrev ym saw siht fi sa ro ,suoicerp saw tnecs sih ekil
delpmas d'I taht woN
.deb elgnis ym ssorca ylpmil sbmil ym delwarps dna
.werg ti - ni dna - neht tub
- ti fo gnileef dna - thguoht eht tuB
elohssa eulb ykrep
'eloh eulb' rehtona no sucof ot gnisoohc dnim ym
- noitseuq tuohtiw erusaelp dnuofwen siht yojne ot ,rednerrus ot ssilb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
tsuJ"  .ti noitseuq
dluoc I"  .emoc ot desufer
.hself evitpecer ym ot enieffac fo zzub railimaf eht gnireviled
gnirahs sevlesmeht dnif syug owt nehw
,kced niam eht ot reddal eht debmilc dna ,rodirroc worran s'pihs eht nwod derednaw
s'ekeZ fo tog I weiv pu esolc eht saw ti ,daetsnI
rood eht esolc ot deirt eh sa delbmuf swap
.etius-ne ynit a dah ti tsael ta tub
,ereht ni pu hsinif ot mih rof hsur on gnieb
-ot ralimissid os ton smees semitemos taht
,depmarc saw pihs eht no derahs ew nibac ehT  .yltcerid
?em gninioj neey etuc a fo daetsni gnizisatnaf
htiw htaerb hcae decal eH
,larutan ,thgir tlef tsuj tI
.yltnatsni dnim ym fo tnorferof eht ot thgir
dehsinif I ssennrobbuts reehs yB
.yawa kool ot drah yllauqe tub ,mih ta kool ot drah saw tI
.revid taerg a gnieb rof nevig erew skram on dna ,ytisrevinu saw ti tuB  .)yvne
yzeerb ylgnisirprus erew ,lluh thgitretaw a ni degrembus gnieb etipsed ,snibac ehT
.llaw etisoppo eht otno elohtrop eht hguorht enohs yeht sa retaw dna sevaw eht ni nus eht fo snoitcelfer eht no gnisucof
.thgil mid eht ni cirbaf eht revo gnippird muc fo sepor kcils ,kciht eht ,swap ym ni
.em revo emoc tsuj dah tahw yb
",netae ydaerla ev'I"
.tcaer su tel sesnes ruo erofeb llits erom elpuoc a dna
sucof ot emit emos dnuof I  ...rO
.rehtegot llew dexim naeco eht dna eH
.esoh eht rednu morf dellac ekeZ "!edud enif s'tI"
.sregnif ym hguorht pils efil ym fo sraey tseb eht gnihctaw ,sselmia dna sselrewop
retal syad eerhT
.ekeZ was eh tsal ecnis
,em dniheb tuhs detlob ylefas rood eht htiw dna enola ,emit siht tuB
- rood eht gnikcol ni detatiseh I
.tniat htooms sih nwod yaw eht lla gninnur retaw fo spord eht nevig
.ruf ym nwod dellewot dna ffo rewohs mraw eht denrut I retfa neve ,dehsulf tlef llits I
.dlrow eht fo stopstoh tsiruot eht neewteb detrad taht staob gniwerc ecnetsixe cidamon a gnivil
.dneirf cinotalp a naht rehto gnihtyna sa erofeb mih fo thguoht t'ndah I
,htaerb hguonevar tsal eno koot I
.eeffoc retlif fo puc a gniruop ,yellag eht ni nwod gnittis
.eulb thgil teews a saw elohliat siH
.yhtrae yltnasaelp
,detaudarg I sa noos sa em revo dehsaw ytilaer fo rewohs dloc ehT
.rood eht tuhs ot yaw a dnuof htob ew ,sesucxe eht neewteb erehwemoS
.enod reven ev'I gnihtemos saw ti hguoht neve ,eloH eulB gnimocpu eht denoitnem su fo rehtieN
.mrahc kcab dial ,citamgine sih aneyh eht evag taht
ym tneverp t'ndluoc
,erutan ni enola gnieb fo cigam eht gniyojne
",yug toh a neeb syawla
emoh ta demees syawla eh ,em ekilnU
"!yrros ,setunim erom eviF"
.pu-tnep tsuj t'nsaw I
- detpure muc kciht fo trups tsrif eht erofeb ezeeuqs ot dedeen neve ylerab I
esiouqrut fo sedahs gnitivni otni gnidlem sretaw eulb eht
,yadiloh a saw sihT
.reenev desilivic ,demoorg sih revo delknirps gnitsud enif a
dexifsnart ylegnarts tlef I
.morf gnimoc eb thgim ti erehw tuo erugif ot gniyrt ,tuoba deffins I
,tsael tA .gnivid htiw od ot gnihton dah ti tuB .seye ym no detnirpmi
"?elohssa eulb a teg eh did lleh eht woH"
.regnevacs larutan a fo ecarg dehsabanu eht htiw nwo sih otno etalp dnoces eht gnippit
.thguoht eht ta hsulf ruf ym rednu niks eht tlef I
.daeh ym otni deppop tahw s'taht - nayC
.mrof sih nwod gninnur seye
,issaveleT yb ”eloH eulB
.ssenelam citoxe sih ni degludni I sa maerts ydaets a otni denrut erp fo spord eht elihw
em
,slewob s'pihs eht ni peed saw nibac ehT .hguoht CA dedeen noitadommocca citsur eht ekil t'nsaw tI
,yad a sevid ruof fo keew a neeb d'tI
.eye-tuhs doog emos retfa smelborp fo tseinroht eht evlos uoy stel ti yaw emas taht ni
?yawa kool ot em rof gnol os nekat ti dah yhW
,aneyh a ekil eta eH
.gnizama dellems eH
".evid txen eht gnidiug em'I
".evif ni pu eb ll'I ,tnemom a
,tuo dehtaerb I sa deretlaf tI
,hcamots ym fo ssenkrad eht ni delgnit tI
,saw rekcup etuc sih ereht
,elcibuc rewohs eht morf tuo deppoh I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
dna raja saw rood euqapo ehT
.rehtie rodirroc eht ni gniregnil
,aes eht ta tuo gnirats hcaeb dnas etihw ,ylenol emos no gniyL
.draobaevil a no tops eerF  .eulb eht fo tuo
gnihton yas ot deganam llits I
raewrednu s'aneyh eht ta derats I
.raen gnihtemos morf gnimoc saw llems siH
,tsehc ym hguorht gnimrow slirdnet toh sti ,taorht ym dehtoos diuqil mraw ehT
- erom yas t'ndid I sratS eht knahT
,gnikniht t'nsaw I
dellecnac sevid owt tsrif :draob eciton eht no egassem eht saw ereht ,hguone eruS
.elzzum ym tsniaga deffuts erew yeht noos dna
.ti fo gnihton thguoht I tub ,ylrae siht no erew yeht taht ddo saw tI
.msitengam fo tros a su evag tnemssarrabmE  .sdrow txen ym
.em naht dellevart erom raf ,lla retfa ,saw ekeZ
eviG"  "?ni uoy ,setunim net ni gnifeirb evid ym gniod m'I"  .flesym tuoba wenk I thguoht I gnihtyreve denrutpu t'ndah elohliat sih fo thgis yrev
.sniol ym revo ssilb fo evaw mraw hcae htiw emac taht llirht eht hsiugnitsid dluoc I ,ycavirp fo tnemom siht nI
:anuaf tekcit gib eht lla htiw gnimmiws aneyh eht fo serutcip
.gniticxE .wen saw sihT
riap dedracsid a :ecruos eht dnuof I litnu gnol ton saw ti dna
reilrae ruo fo ssensuovren dna tnemssarrabme eht ssimsid ot ,sevaw eht fo yaws eltneg eht yb ylno detnecca ,ecnelis taht ni ysae saw tI
yb dah evah thgim niarb ym snoitseuq yna gnissapyb
...seert mlap gniyaws eht htaenrednu reeb a gnippis
.yellag eht fo renroc eht ni skoon eerf eht fo eno ni nwod tas dna
.ecnatsid yb dehsinimid ssel on erew em nihtiw sedit eht tub
tuo erugif ot yrt em tel taht gnisselb a ,elzzum sih otni yawa doof eht gnillevohs
.rednow dnim eht tel ot hguone eltbus dnoyeb
.gnifeirb eht rehtegot gnittup kced no eb ll'I .looC"
dna raeg yknulc eht etipsed dna
,revo puc eraps eht dehsup eH ".llifer
eno siht piks esaelp
,yddub gniht eruS"
.retnuocne
.lla ti yb delbuortnu saw taht ,yteicos dna sdrow dnoyeb ,em fo trap redlo emos saw ti spahreP .gnivol dna
yleritne wodniw eht revo gnihsaw sevaw eulb peed eht
.noititeper dna ytirailimaf gnitrofmoc htiw edisa gnidilg aes talf rorrim eht
.wohs ,yltnatropmi erom dna ,yas ot ytnelp dah syawla eh tub
eht fi sA .ffo hsurb ot ysae os tsuj saw reilrae deneppah dah tahw fi sA .gnihton saw ti fi sA .rood eht dniheb morf dehgual ekeZ ",seirrow oN"  "!ni emoc t'nod ,haeY"  "?ereht ni uoy ,yddub yeH"  .thgilf lluf ot em thguorb rood eht no kconk A
.gninrom siht ereht rednu dekcik nettog evah tsum yehT
",rewohs a barg ot gniog m'I"
,sruof lla otno nwod denael I os
,nepo rood nibac eht deppans dna deb eht ffo tpael I htlaets dna deeps htiW
,aneyh eht tuoba em dlot ti sgniht etamitni eht lla gniruovas
,sdapwap ym dlacs diuqil toh eht tlef I nehw pots ot derebmemer I
.raewrednu s'ekeZ fo edam d'I ssem ymaerc
.efil ot gnilkcirt daehrewohs eht fo ssih eht dna rood eht yb delffum erew sdrow s'aneyh ehT ".yellag
saw tI .enog raf os saw dnim ym dalg saw I
gniht eht saw tI
.enola maerd derahs ruo ecno saw tahw werc ot gniyrt
"?ereht ni enod uoy t'nerA"
otni erp fo spord kciht dekael dna debborht kcid drah ym erofeb
.sraey ni emit tsrif eht rof dneirf tseb ym was I sa toidi na ekil gninnirg
".enif s'ti dias I"
.eno tog s'enoyreve
.egap yrruFoS rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
.etad ot noitasrevnoc yratnemgarf
.htaerb ym gnidloh
.toh os tlef ruf ym rednu niks eht
.niaga ehtaerb ot elba eb reven d'I ekil ,lufgnul ydaeh rehtona gnilaets dna cirbaf eht tsniaga tuons ym gniffuts
.kniht ot ytiliba ym gnivlossid ,sgnul ym dellif tnecs siH  !sratS gnikcuF
.elyts tseinniks eht otni snaej fo tuc gnirettalfnu yna tuoba tsuj decuder shgiht gniglub s'ohw
yhw tuo erugif ot gniyrt
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
- syad eseht teg nac uoy sa uaetsuoC ot esolc sa si ecneirepxe elohw ehT
,ediug dna rotcurtsni gnivid a sa krow dnuof eh em dlot eH
.ti eman uoy - skrahs ,syar atnam ,seltrut
.gniht eno ylno tnaem tI
?emoc ot tnaW .llota
.niaga evila tlef I .sratS
.ytpme saw ti thguoht I
saw I erofeb neve taht wenk I
,raelc ylgnisirprus saw dnim yM
tahw tub - eciohc a eb ot tog s'taht ,naem I"
.ythguan fo hsad yhtlaeh a dnA
,elohliat s'ekeZ htiw ecaf ot ecaf gnitteg fo ssendrawkwa eht tsuj saw noitcaer ym
ti dna ,thgil gninrom tfos eht thguac yeht sa retaw fo spord llams htiw denetsilg gnir sih
,enod ytterp dekool ekeZ ,nees tsuj d'I tahw morf
,deknilb I emit yrevE
.hgih detfil liat buN
.ti tuoba kniht ot tnaw t'ndid I
- elttil a retaw htuom ym edam eH
-naht rehtar ,knip
htiw tsrif - erutarepmet eht htiw gnilddif yb noitcartsid emos dnif ot deirt I
,ereht dna ,htaerb peed rehtona koot I
delbuortnu saw I ,ylegnartS
,sgniht ehtoos dluow peelS
s'ekeZ"  .elttes ot demees ti erom eht ,ti tuoba ekops dna ,ti tuoba thguoht I erom ehT
.kcab ti detaeper I ",yrroS"
- drah dna peed dehtaerb I
nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI
.meht htaenrednu os erom dna ,sevaw eht no
.drah tih ytilaer cimedacA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
eno saw ti noitnem ot detcelgen d'eh tub
,naeco ylenol eht revo sesir nus eht sa eeffoc kciuq a gnivah ,ma6 ta pu gnikaw s'ti
koot wap yM .eloh sih ,sllab sih ,htaehs sih fo stnecs eht htob ni gnihtaerb
.nibac ruo sdrawot dna sriats eht nwod kcab dedaeh I  ".doog sdnuoS"
sih fo tnecs hserf on
.detnurg dna worbeye na desiar I
,llarevo 1.2 a htiw
.saw eh ereht ,emit siht tpecxE
,tfirda ,raey lanif ym ni yb deparcs I
,peed ni dehtaerb I .dettimda I
.su neewteb yradnuob yrosnes taht gnirrulb
,dehgis eh ",em stiuS"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
derettat emos hguorht gniwap
morf eno ylno eht saw ekeZ
,ksed a dniheb deppart lruc ym tog stroffe ym lla dna
dewap-erab deklaw I ,gnidraob retfa sruoh evlewt dna ,tekcit enalp niagrab a no saw I
".stiustew rieht ni sessip enoyreve evid gnol a no woh ekil
***  .mossolb gnileef gnisilatnat sih tel dna seye ym desolc I
,kced pot eht no tas dna  ylrae ekow eH
,yltnatropmi tsom dna ,thgis ni eno on ees ot feiler ni delbmert I
.raey dnoces sih fo dne eht
.gniliec eht ta pu derats dna
,sllaw eht ni skcarc eht revo derepap niarb ym fo edis lanoitar eht elihw deredluoms ylno dah sgnihT
!tnemyojne rof eb syawla dluohs syadiloh dna
- gnirolpxe tpek I ,oS
,em revo yaws dleh meht fo rehtieN
.wam yrgnuh sih otni etalp sih morf gge fo skcelf lanif eht deparcs eh sa
,em dniheb desolc rooD
,sih ot tnecs ym dedda I sa erised dna deen ni gnilworg
,raewrednu sih otni gnitoohs ,gniog tpek I dna
?tnecs ...sih ti sI
,dnoces a tsuj detsal ti ytilaer nI
elttil a dna( noitarimda htiw em dellif taht ecarg dednepsus
,tonk ym ezeeuqs dna kcoc ym ekorts ot deunitnoc I sA
.dnim ym ta dewalc taht lla ti tuoba gnisuma gnihtemos saw ereht tub
.lasuora gniworg ym morf emoc evah thgim taht snoitseuq yna yb debrutrepnu ,ecneserp sih fo noisulli eht yb detrofmoc erom saw I ,llews ot detrats htaehs ym sa nevE .ecneserp sih fo otnemem lausnes taht gnidloh
,yllatnem pu syug gnizis saw I aedi eht no llewd ot ton deirt I