".yltnecer driew lla gnitca neeb ev'uoY"
,skeehc sih neewteb tuons ym sserp ot pu gninael
.pmur sih desaet wap ym sa seye ym dniheb detnirpmi ecaf gnilims sih fo egami eht ,dennirg I
tpmetta ytsah ym
"?siht ekil maerd a roF"
kcab em dessik ekeZ
.yddub ruoy ot esolc kcits dna
.em otni erew uoy rehtehW"
.niaga ecno neht ,ecno
sehsalps lareves yb dewollof ,skcehc evid-erp fo rettahc elbatummi lanif eht saw ereht ,thgis fo tuo dna su htaeneB
.egap yrruFoS rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.draobaevil gnivid a no mih nioj ot
- yas ot esle tahw wonk t'ndid I tub
,eugnot ym fo pit eht no gnidliub sdrow txen ym tlef I
gnimocpu eht dna
",kcab og ot tnaw t'nod I tuB"
- gnorts saw thguac gnitteg
.sremialcsid sa llew sa ecneirepxe dnamed uoy yhw s'taht tub
,em ta delims neey eht
.setteuohlis krad otni liated tsom gniredner
.tniartser elttil saw erehT
ot uoy ksa ot gniog t'nsaw I ,naem I .adniK"
,ylkciuq tiustew ym otni dezeeuqs I sa teiuq saw I
elbat ssem eht dnuora gnikool ,desuap aneyh ehT
.lliw ti erus m'I"
"?gniod uoy erew htrae no tahW"
.ynoga ekil dessap dnoces hcaE
.retaw eht deretne werc eht fo tser eht sa
.ruf sih gnikorts ,dias I
.spil ym ot niaga ecno esolc gnihsurb elzzum sih
dedoolf hcihw sevac morf demrof er'yehT"
.yllufdeen delworg I
.yromem tnatsid a sgnul ym ni ezeerb-aes
,ezeeuqs kciuq a esoh rotalfni s'DCB ym evag I
.nwod dna pu saw yaw hcihw fo esnes yna gnignirb selbbub ria ruo fo tnemevom eht
",neve etatiseh t'nod uoY"
".bahaD ni eno eht naht ward retteb si eloH eulB ruoy ,yllanosreP
,enam ym fo tuo dehsaw tlas ,ksed
?maerd detrawht rehtona otni
,htaehs sih htiw deyalp dna pu dehcaer I .duol dna
ydob ylepahs sih fo weiv tcefrep eht no rehto eht dna eguag htped ym no eye eno gnipeek
.yrolg lluf sti ot derotser eb dluow liat ylruc ym tnaem ti taht erac neve t'ndid I
.elzzum gnitiaw ym evoba yltcerid derevoh ssa sih litnu
"?tnedicca na ti saW"  ".dalg m'I dnA"
- nwo ym tem elzzum detrap sih sa eugnot etaciled sih ees llits dluoc I .nwo ym gnihctam
.moolg eht morf ni dedaf sllaw s'elohknis eht litnu ,rehtruf maws eW
,ega eci tsal eht fo dne eht ta esor slevel aes nehw
.esle enoyreve naht don ot regnol tnemom a em koot tI
,taob eht fo edispot eht no delttes dah aneyh ehT
"...gninrom siht uoy fo kool eht dekil yllaer I"
.enacirruh a ekil gnidnuos enam ym htiw gniyalp ezeerb teiuq eht ;mih raeh ot deniarts nwo yM
,ylteiuq deksa ekeZ "?I saw woH"
,puorg eht ni enoyreve htiw tcatnoc eye edam aneyh ehT ".yddub
,stnerruc detcepxe tuoba eton a
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.em ot esolc gnilffuhs emit siht
,elddim eht ni deggel-ssorc tas I
,erohs rieht ot miws dna draobrevo pmuj ot detnaw adnik I
,seye ym desolc I nehw ereht saw thgis ehT
.htaehs ym ni ssenthgit railimaf taht gnileef ,deksa I
.kced evid eht otno nwod gnippoh ,deprihc eH
aneyh ehT "?wonk uoy ...reve uoy evaH"
,efil fo yarra hcir a htiw dellif mir eritne eht
...ti dekil yllaer I"  .ti rof og
tsol mottob eht dna
.llydi laciport ni deyaws seert mlap eht sa meht nopu gniwolg
.rehtruf teg em tel
".ti derevocsid uoy noitnem ot togrof uoY"
rieht gnitset - skcehc evid-erp rieht nageb dna
- elpmis etiuq si yksuh eht rof noitseuq eht woN
.tbuod fo dees gnirulla na etiuq dewos
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
flow gnikool yffurcs yrev eno ,sdinac fo xim yeltom a - seiceps fo egnar a erew yehT .werc evid delbmessa eht ta
.tlef I tahw rof tbuod ro raef on saw ereht erehw
elzzum ym neve ekil gnileef
.eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo em ta gnikool mih thguac I
”eloH eulB s’ekeZ“   yojne esaelP
- llits mih tsniaga rehtruf elzzum ym desserp I dna ,mih edisni peed
ruf sih fo skaerts nat eht
.kcab yaw on ni tluser dluow ni gnivid taht dna
.enim no ruf erab siH .su neewteb ycamitni larutan eht etaicerppa ot gnisuap
sdrow sih ot noitapicitna yddig fo egde na saw ereht ,kaeps did eh nehw tub ,elihw a rof teiuq saw ekeZ
...siht liops ot tnaw t'nod I"
,aes malc eht ssorca demmiks taob eht sa setunim evif trohs a saw tI .BIR
.ruoloc fo murtceps lluf eht htiw su gnilzzad ,demoolb slaroc eht esor ylwols ew sa tub
,psag sselhtaerb a htiW
.tnelis deniamer eh tub ,edisni dih I gninaem repeed eht desnes eh spahreP
.yawyna emoc evah dluow I"
.llits retaerg saw mih ni degludni I sa seye desolc ym dniheb derekcilf taht thgil eht ,daehrevo srats gnimoolb
.aeS ossagraS ediw eht ssorca derats dna edis eht ot daeh ym gnuws I
.scisyhp morf semoc - eulb
",ecneirepxe emitefil a ni ecno a si eloh eulb a gniviD"
.evom txen sih rof detiaw I sa
.regnol rof deniwtne niamer t'ndluoc seidob ruo taht detatirri su fo htob
"-ti tuo tuo gniht a ekam t'nod ,esaelp tsuj - enif s'taht - ton fI"
.mottob eht dehcaer sah eno on etad ot dna
.elttob nworb eht gniniard yllacitcarp ,reeb fo plug a koot I
rewoprevo dluow tlas dna aes fo llems eht gnipoh
- sDCB ,sksam ,snif ,sthgiew gnikcehc ,sknat ria rieht fo tnecs dna etsat eht ,srotaluger
",sfeer lla ton s'ti os ,llits yteirav fo tib a sgniht eviG
.rehtruf eciov ym esiar ot ton gniyrt ,desserp I
gnidneterp ,sgel ym revo dedlof smra
,kced eht tsniaga nwod em dehsup wap mrif ,gnorts siH  " .evid a naht
.hsac htiw hsawa
- ekaseman peed riehT
,deddon I ",spahreP"
,llits rehtruf noitisop sih gnitfihs yb stsetorp ym decnelis
,deksa I "?tahw rednoW"
.rehtegot emit ruo lla ni ot deeh diap ro deciton reven d'I taht gnihtemos
.ecno smaerd ym hsurc dlrow eht tel I"
",eloH eulB eht fo mir eht gnitriks
.leef em edam eh woh no gnisucof
,erom gnihtemos rof yrt ot
".ti rof esigolopa t'noD"
,niaga deksa ekeZ
,aneyh eht dniheb esolc pu maws dna
etipsed etalucammi dekool lla ohw( stac fo lufdnah a
.derepsihw I ",erom tnaw I"
.ylkciuq ekops I ".oN"
:ecafrus eht no kcab erew ew hguone nooS
.ylkciuq oot raf dessap setunim ytxiS
ew sa kced eht no talf gniyl ,kcab sih otno revo dellor ekeZ
,god.ecioveht ta
,detalfni ti sa gnissih tekcaj ym fo kcab eht no sevlav eht
.walc prahs a htiw ffo pac eht dekcilf eH
",ot evah t'nod uoy tub ,sknahT"  ".yawyna
.deplug I ".yako s'taht fI"
",kcab uoy yap ll'I"
,tesnus eht gnihctaw ,noziroh eht ot tuo gnikool tpek I .srae ym tsap degrus ti sa deraor llits
.ylteiuq dias ekeZ
"-yrt ot tnaw I tuB"
",uoy fo gnikniht saw I"
.nus gnittes eht tsniaga snoitcerid lla ni dednetxe taht sretaw latsyrc ,eruza yb deknalf neerg dlareme fo snobbir
...oS"  .ruovref sseldrow htiw
.yliratnemom dehsulb ekeZ ",seY"
neey ehT  ".hguonE" .spih sih delggiw eH
"?niaga em ees ot tnaw ...uoY"
.mih edisni deppils won
delriws eugnot yM
.stnemele eht sa eerf dna ,evila ,kciuq stnemevom sih ,aes nepo eht gnoma emoh ta
.tnemeerga ni deddon yeht nehw ylno no gnivom
"?eb thgim taht kniht uoy od tahW"
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.rekram kcalb dna ,der ,eulb ni draobetihw s'yellag eht no nward d'eh etuor eht gnola tseretni fo serutaef dna
,tnemom a koot eW
.em gnigdun ,daeh sih detlit
,rae ym otni dehtaerb ekeZ
peels ot ffo gnitfird
.redluohs eht no mih gnittap ,deddon I ".lliw
"?thgir lla gnihtyreve sI"
.eson ym no htaerb toh sih leef dluoc I
,sdileye ym tsniaga pu llew sraet tlef yllautca I .deilper I
..."  ...srae ym revo gnihsaw eciov sih fo dnuos tnasaelp eht gniyojne daetsni
,ria rof gnipsag ecarbme taht morf decafrus eW
***  .eromyna redro ot woh aedi on
tseb sih ni ekops eh sa mih dniheb gnihctiwt liat bun ,dennirg ekeZ
regnorts gniworg
ycneiciffe desitcarp htiw strohs sih fo tuo gnidils ,em fo pot no noitisop sih detfihs eH
- emit emas eht ta werg dna knarhs I ekil tlef I  ".uoy
dneirf dlo sih yb deksa saw rotarran ruo ,emit tsaL
pu ti dekcip eh taht hguone
.rufdaeh sih morf kcalb dna elprup fo skcol gniyaws ,tfos eht dniheb neddih
.BIR eht fo edis eht ffo kcab denael dna KO dengis I
.em gnirehtob yllaer saw tahw yas ot woh wonk t'ndid I
.aedi yllis a saw ti tub
.enot tnemegagne tneilc ,yppep
seigolohtna psarG ruO nihtiW snevaeH ehT
t'ndid I ekas sih rof tub
,dne eht nI .egnulp eht ekat ot enoyna gnihsup s'eno oN
,noisremmi ym dedlareh em dnuora selbbub fo rumrum  dna
,sertem 001 dnoyeb sevid lacinhcet yna neeb t'nevah erehT
",taht
.seirareniti erutuf ot skcerw emos dda ylbaborp dluohs eW"
,anuaf dna arolf detcepxe tuoba stcaf
.ssik ruo fo noitcennoc eht hctam ot thguos seidob ruo sa rehto hcae dnuora gnidlof smra ruo
.ssik rehtona rof ni gninael dna mih fo pot no gnillor
.ssecorp eht ni gnispalloc sfoor rieht
"?dneps uoy did hcum woH"  "-yap
,mih gnitae tpek I sa htgnel kcils ydaerla sih gnikorts
,ti kcuf saw yas dluoc daeh ym lla tub ,sdrow eht dnif ot deirt I elihw nepo gnuh htuom yM
- gnieb fo ycamirp larutan eht ot nruter
.eloh eulb rehto sih tuoba sthguoht ym gniciov diova ot gniyrt ,eugnot ym tib I
,ecipicerp yldlrowrehto emos revo derevoh ew taht gnileef yllis eht wollaws ot drah saw tI
”eloH eulB s’ekeZ“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.tsehc ym pu rehtruf flesmih detfihs eH
"?eloh eulb siht erolpxe em pleh ot gniog uoy era
"?eerf saw tekcit ym dias uoy thguoht I"
2 fo 2 traP ,issaveleT yb
.enot egnahc ot tnemom a gnikat ,desuap ekeZ ".mottob
.naeco eht fo tser eht morf deretlehs
.skcehc yddub nwo ruo tuoba tnew ew sa edis ym gnihsurb yltneg liat sih
.kcab og ot ti tnaw t'ndid I dna ,tnemom siht liops ot tnaw t'ndid I
- peed ylniatrec si eloH eulB s'ulevroT"
.nwod gnidlof srae sih ,dettimda aneyh eht
;esnepsus etelpmoc ni erew ew tnemom a roF
?ti yas tsuj eh t'naC .thguoht I .em eraps ,sratS
"?thgir ,gnihtemos saw erus evid tahT"
,elbuort ni gnitteg elpoep tuoba deirrow erew uoy wonk I"
.mih ot esolc os eb ot ytinutroppo eht rof lufetarg
.tnemom eht hguorht tuc noissimda siH
etiuq ...tsuj saw tI"
.elihw a rof uoy nwonk ev'I"
"...aedi na evah I"  .dehtaerb I
.gnivid lanoitaercer fo stimil eht dnoyeb llew si siht ,esruoc fO"
,taorht sih ni delbmur lworg siH
.snif sih htiw delddif eh sa yawa gnikool ,dehsulb eh
.setunim ytxis tsael ta rof
rerevocsid s'etis eht htiw evid a no gniog tuB"
dna ssenkrad eht etipseD
,noitnetta diap llits I
.koot I reeb fo - plug neht - pis eht etipsed
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.xobeci eht morf reeb rehtona flesmih gnibbarg
.seye sih gnibbur ,deffins ekeZ
doolb ym tub ,yalc tew kciht fo edam saw ti ekil dedduht traeh yM
- snoitcerid lla ni detpurretninu dehcterts ytuaeb stI
,eulb nepo eht otni tuo dehcterts snaf aes tsaV
,mih eveileb ot dehca ydob yM
.meht gnidiova tpek I tub nwo ym rof gnihcraes seye sih leef dluoc I .niaga desserp eH ".elihw
ni dnif nac uoy krow esohw ,issaveleT yb
euh eulb peed a ot gnitfihs sretaw wollahs ,raelc eht
,retaw raelc eht ni thgis ruo dnoyeb repeed gnidnetxe ,reehs erew yehT
".iouq sias en ej ,niatrec a sdda
,wap sih dezeeuqs dna tuo dehcaer I
niaga KO dellangis I sertem 03 dehcaer ew nehW  .woleb rehtruf
.srats eht ta pu dekool htob
kle eht tuoba gnikniht ylraelc
.ria ssecxe eht depmud neht dna
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,issaveleT yb
d'ohw( kle ffub ,llat a dna ,)tlas eht
.spih sih htiw hcamots ym gnilddarts
".kcab gniog ton m'I"  .pael a koot I oS
,dneirf a naht erom ekeZ nees reven d'eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.yad eht fo syar lanif eht ni gnimaelg
.nwo ym fo demahsanu em edam taht
.su fo owt eht neewteb ezeerb eltneg ehT
.setamitse tseb ruo morf sertem 002 revo
.ezeerb yrtniw tnegruser a no mossolb gnirps a ekil dereviuq eh ,emac ekeZ nehW
erutnevda rehtona enifnoc ro
pihs eht fo senifnoc desolc eht ni retnuocne drawkwa na tub
.wenk I gnihtyreve fo senifnoc eht edisa tsac yllanif I sa tbuod otni nworht esrevinu eht ni ezis evitaler ym
,erusserp ria ruoy no hctaw esolc a peek
evoba tnatsid saw ecafrus ehT
.elzzum ym ni rotaluger ym kcuts dna deilper I ",enif m'I"
skoobgol nwo rieht rof seton rieht pu dehsinif werc eht fo tser ehT
- htrof dna kcab gnitrad slaohs lufruoloc fo dairym eht fo tnuoc tsol I
,enerpoen kcalb ni desacne
"-rednow ot gnitrats saw I dna ,ereh keew a neeb d'tI"
,sliat rieht htiw sehcnarb eht ta gnihctulc yletaciled sesrohaes ymgyp ynit
.gnihctiwt srae ,deggurhs ekeZ  ".hguorht
,swollahs eht ni evid thgin a gniod er'yehT"
,noziroh eht ot resolc knurhs tesnus eht sa degnit serutaef sih ,em neewteb pag eht desolc aneyh ehT
nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI
"!flesruoy yojne ot rebmemer ,enod ytefas eht htiw dnA !dooG"
.wap gnipleh sih htiw
.detnurg ekeZ ",lleW"
gniklat erom on eb dluow ereht taht feiler gnignirb
,sdrow sih fo gninaem eht ni tseretni tsol d'I tub
".ti ekil etiuq gnihtyna nees reven ev'I .gnikathtaerb
,og uoy repeed eht os ,tsrif murtceps thgil eht fo shtgnelevaw regnol sbrosba retaW
hguone nooS .yvne ym niatnoc ylerab dluoc I
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf
.derevesrep I ",haeY"
.ezeerb gnineve eht ni ylgnirulla gnireviuq skcol kciht ,edis eht ot enam elprup sih dehsurb elihwnaem aneyh ehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.dellems eh naht retteb neve detsat eh ,nevaeH
,sertem ytriht fo htped mumixam a ot retupmoc evid ruoy teS
fo raef eht ,llits tub
.eguag htped ruoy no eye na peeK .rebmemer os
",emit rehtona ebyaM"
yticilpmis dehsimelbnu rieht ni dna
".kcab og ot evah d'uoy neht kcab wenk I
:sgnifeirb evid tsom fo eugolatac lausu eht hguorht deunitnoc ekeZ  "...ertaehtihpma
,ylduol dehgis dna pu doots eH
,dluoc I pord yreve rof mih deklim dna ,hcnelc yreve sih tlef I
yas t'ndid I"  "?naf a toN"  .depoord ffulf kcen sih dna deppid srae sih - mih truh msaisuhtne fo kcal ym woh ees dluoc I .ylper detaleb ym dna flesym htiw detartsurf ,dehgis I ".egnahc a yletinifed s'tI"  .pihs eht fo trap ylno ffats a otni gniyarts fo aedi eht htiw elbatrofmocnu wohemos saw I taht
,deilper aneyh eht ",derednow I"
",esiw ytsedom elttil a derugif I"
- tsiser t'ndluoc I
"-t'nod esaelp ,kool tub ,reilrae tuoba yrros m'I"
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,erom ecno yawa pils sdrow tel I
.evid taht edulcni dluohs uoy kniht I tuB"
- lufituaeb dekool eh ,sratS
...regnol tnemom eno tsuj tsal dluow eh taht gnihsiw
senifnoc rieht fo eerf gnippils yllanif
,ecnahc a ekat dna pael eht ekam eh seod
"...siht tuoba em llet t'ndid uoY"
.htaerb txen sih no tnecs ym no
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.)skcerw yna gnivid nehw yaw eht ni teg t'ndluow yeht os
eno siht piks esaelp
.reilrae setunim
.rae na gnikcilf ,deksa ekeZ
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.kaeps ot dah su fo eno hguone noos tub ,tcefrep saw su neewteb ecnelis ehT
.nwo ym tsniaga tsehc sih gnihctulc
".niaga os od ti tel ot gniog ton m'I
",reviled lliw etis eht taht erusserp fo paeh elohw a ,ylevitanretla ,rO"
.mih htaenrednu thgiled ni gnilggirw
ti ees ot elba eb dna ,tnaw uoy tahw wonk uoy tsurt ot tog ev'uoy
htaerb ym dleh I
.liat bun suoegrog taht htaenrednu flesym gniyrub
".ereh pu gnimoc s'eno oN"
.derepsihw I ",haeY"
gniog eb t'now eW
.traeh ym fo taeb citarre eht morf gniyaws ,yddig saw I
.kcoc dettonk sih fo hcni yreve dekrow dna dezeeuqs swap yM .gnir kcils sih dehcterts dna desserp elzzum yM
.nwonknu serac sti dna dlrow eht fo tser eht
eulb gnitanimulli siht fo sertem ytriht tsrif eht nihtiw ees ot ytnelp s'ereht tub ,shtped fo stros esoht raen erehwyna
,)tlas deird htiw deggolc yletulosba saw ruf sih(
,ereh pu em nioj ot uoy deksa dna reeb taht uoy dednah I nehw taht gnileef a dah I"
rehto gnihtemos ni detseretni erew uoy
,rehtegot dnalsi na no enola erew ew eveileb dluoc I seye ym desolc I fI
.smra s'rehto hcae ni
.ecnayonna ni seye ym dekcilf I
.pirt eht rof sreltna sih tuc d'taht
.gnissap ruo hguorht derebmuls sllaw eht ni skcarc neewteb deltsen seltrut ypeels elihw
net morf ecart lla yawa hsaw ot
.snel eht ssorca avilas eht gnibbur dna ksam ym otni gnittips
.elttob reeb nworb eht morf giws a koot dna delims ekeZ
draobaevil siht rof yllacificeps sreltna sih tuc yllufesoprup
".maerd a no sgnivas ym derednauqs tsuj d'I rehtehW
a dniheb kcab eb d'I
,enim dnuof seye sih nehw derevihs I
detnaw I .erolpxe ot nuf gnihtemos ro ,nuf emos rof gnipoh tsuj t'nsaw I woH
.spil sih no em detsat eh sa seye sih ot ytisnetni eht ees
”eloH eulB s'ekeZ“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
gnol lworg ym edam taht ssenmrif a htiw mih tsniaga elzzum ym gniyrub thgiew sih ,em no nwod delttes eh sa delbmert htaerb s'ekeZ
dna tonk sih eerf gnillup
dah I taht sdrow fo lluf dlrow a
retaw looc eht fo hsalps ehT
.eerf gnikop ydaerla pit detniop sih ,htaehs pmulp sih desaet I sa gniregnil
eht otno nwod delffuhs dna raeg evid ruo otni deppilc ew sa su neewteb gnah ecnelis elbaplap eht tel eW
.kced eht fo esab eht ta reppucs eht hguorht gnilgnad swap
.su neewteb pag eht tuoba ylgninoitseuq srae sih dekcilf ekeZ woh gnirongi ,deggurhs I
,ylkciuq deilper I
.dekrims eH "?haey hO"
thgil elgnis a ton ,denokceb dnal fo srevils yarts wef a ,ecnatsid eht ni raF
.yterus hcus htiw ekops eH
,tsehc sih nwod wap ym liart ot pu gnihcaer
".semoceb euh eulb eht rekrad eht
.sedis lla ta deppal eruza thgindim ,peed ehT
,noitasrevnoc eht gnireets niaga ecno ,dias ekeZ
.tlah a ot dewols BIR eht sa elzzum sih morf rotaluger sih gnillup ,deksa ekeZ "?ko uoY"  .eloh eht fo ertnec eht ot dessorc ew sa
t'nerew mih ekil sediug evid wenk I ,denrae eh hcum woh wonk t'ndid I hguoht nevE
,mih htaenrednu nwo ym tsniaga delggiw I elihw