yletelpmoc spots eh semitemoS
.uoy tnaw I tuB“
.gnirats m’I ,dog ,hO
.kool ereh-lakcaj-a-ereht-si lacizziuq a mih evig I tub
)su swolla wal eht nehw( evah su fo edutitlum a ,lla ta ton
,dlrow laer eht ni kcaB
,ssap I sa rood eht ot txen llaw eht tsniaga gninael si tar gnidnetrab ehT
remrahC eniuqE eht
,thgin eht otni knils I sa seye s’dahC teem flesym ekam t’nac I .taerter ytsah a
.ynapmoc emos esu dluoc uoy thguoht tsuj I .yrros m’I“
.gnihsur ton era eW
”?emoh em ekat ot tnaw eh dluow dlrow eht ni yhw os
.niaga ecno drah gnihtaerb
.em ssik ot tnaw ot mih tnaw I ,taht naht eroM
.gninihw dna gnitnap mih evah I
.si eman ym tahw wonk I
,nac I sa raf sa nwod edils I
yawflah tuoba ti ekam ylno nac I
,mih fo hcni yreve leef I
.sleuqes sti dna
erusserp fo noitacilppa eltneg A
,ylluferac ,yltneG
.tresed eht rof smetsys noitamalcer retaw tra eht fo etats ngised ot ,shtnom eerhT“
,ecivda evig ot edoc rednetrab dercas eht tsniaga s’ti ,woN“
.kcor gorp s08 emos
.rehtegot sserp ew sa snaom dna spsag elttil sih fo dnuos tfos ,teews eht raeh tsomla nac I
tekcop ym ni kcab enohp eht evohs I
taeb ot em rof emit s’ti ezingocer I dna
.ekil si esruoc niam eht tahw ees s’tel
revihs ydob-elohw a htiw em sdrawer eh dna
.gnidliub eht otni su sehsur dna dnah eht yb em sekat dahC
.egaugnal namuh yna ni debircsnart eb nac eveileb t’nod I taht dnuos a sekam eH
.mih ta pu kool I nehw em sllet eh
.tnorfretaw eht no erehwemos sevil eh ylsuoivbo esuaceb
.emoh og dna pu ti kcap ot emit s’ti
srotceted latem lacol lareves ffo gnittes ylbissop—
,rotavele eht pu edir eht gnimaerdyad rehtob t’nod I
”,yrros os m’I ,ekaJ ,hO“
.doog sa tsuj s’taht dna
.mih morf elgnad I sa pu flesmih gnidloh s’eh woh dnim reven—
?dahC ,tiaW .knilb I
.seye sih nepo ot ygrene eht pu skrow dahC erofeb sessap tnemom rehtonA
.msagro ym htiw stsehc ruo fo htob gnittalps
,rotarran reliart eivom a no sgnoleb taht eciov a ni ,syas eh ”,orb ,yeH“
.hcae skcub derdnuh a tsoc hcihw dna
.setunim net dilos a rof enohp ym ta gnirats neeb ev’I taht erawa emoceb I .gnihtemos rO
,ssik a rof ni snael eh sa selkcuhc eH
.detcepxe I taht yticapac gnul erom htiw
.ngis a rof ti ekat I dna
.lluf ylrettu siht ,etelpmoc siht
,rehto eht ni su sparw neht
?sgnicreip eugnot owt evah eh seoD .ylkciht syas eh
.rood eht skcolnu eh sa hctorc sih ta erats I
,dahC dnuora msaps I ,yliratnulovnI
.yab gniremmihs-thgin eht ot yaw eht lla ees nac uoy dna
.taht dias I fi em htiw yrgna eb dluow tsipareht yM
,kcoc sih no retsaf wap ym gnivom trats I
.thgin yrrats ,sselnoom eht ta
”.ereht ni tog taht woh aedi oN“
”,rednaxela ydnarB“
.smra sih otni tlem flesym tel I dna
,sdnah dloh od ew tub
.tuo elttob eht llup I sa yas I
,enam dediarb sih otni sregnif ym pils I
.raeppasid sehtolc ruo dna nepo rood eht steg dahC
repeed dna repeed ,elzzum ym otni sedils dahC .nwod evid I
.daehrevo gnilkraps srats thgirb eht
,ereht em rof gnitiaw gnihton s’ereht tub
.sgnicreip eugnot owt sah yletinifed eH .snirg eH
.liat ym fo esab eht no gnitser sllab sih
dna dnah s’dahC sekat neht dna
.eugnot dna sregnif htiw kcoc sih fo erutxet eht gnileef
otni seuges smrA nepO ,xobekuj eht nO
dna llihc eht tsniaga dleihs ot htob
,em gnikcuf ni detseretninu si niarb ym neve fI
ton m’I epoh I ,kool …I
hctorc ym fo tnorf ni sehtolc ym gnidloh flesym enigami I
.dnuos eht elfits dna yrt ot elzzum ym revo dnah a palc I dna
,emit emas eht ta htob od su fo emoS
.htrig sih ot tsujda I sa yrc a elffits dna redduhs I
?sseug I ,iH .tahw wonk t’nod I
.taorht ym otni nwod sedils doowtsurhT dahC dna
.drawkwa taht eb ot ygrene eht pu krow ot drah s’ti tub ,mih raeh ot ton gnidneterp redisnoc I .syas eh
.bac eht ni dnuora loof d’ew ,ylsuoivbO
,ekacfeeb taht fo gnivres a tnaw uoy fI“
”?netfo ereh emoc uoY“
,dnats dna kcab ti evohs I
.resolc pets a gnikat ,yas I
.gurhs dna wols I
,dahC laer eht ot revo kcab ecnalg A
.taht yas t’nod I
na teg I ,liat sih gniggaW
.reeb a gnippis si ylgniskcap-xiS dahC erehw
.ytic eht revo tuo kool swodniw gib ehT
.yletaidemmi tsomla ti pord I dna
,rab eht hguorht yrrac t’now ti taht os wol eciov sih ,syas eh
?em tuoba kniht knuh siht tsum tahw ,dog ,hO
,enoemos htiw emoh og t’nac I fi
htimsnrop retsam a
,sredluohs ym no thgiew gnitrofmoc taht enigami tsuj nac I
tsomla ,dlim a tog s’tI
,kniw a em sreffo eH .mih llet I
ruos fo tnih tnasaelpnu yleritne ton a ,yksum elttil a—
,edistuo digirf ot yllihc morf enog s’tI
ma I naht rellat daeh doog a ,esroh a s’eH
.daeh ym fo pot eht otni srumrum eh ”,uoy knahT“
,gnihtyna yas nac I erofeB
kcor m’I taht erawa emoceb I
,ni sevil dahC enigami I sodnoc yztir eht fo edistuo tlah a ot sllup bac eht emit eht yB
.peelsa eb tsum miJ .gnihtoN
.reel fo riah a tsuj htiw dexim ebyam
,kool lacizziuq a mih evig I
.yawa tfird ot stnaw tsuj em fo trap a dna
.eruliaf rettu dna
.smra s’dahC ni peelsa llaf I erofeb ,rumrum I
.em fo edam s’eh ssem eht seips eh sa kcab gninnip srae ,syas eh
.noitcaer ym yb delffab elttil a skool dutsuaeB yldahC ”?tahW ?woh …I“
.derovalf yrrehc si dahC .ti kcuF
.ti rof pleh on s’erehT
.ti ta doog gnitteg m’I .stnap s’dahC
,ekil setsat reziteppa eht tahw si siht fi ,lleW
.ti deknat yletulosba
,teerts ylenol eht nwod egdurt dna thgir nrut I
.ti rof snalp gib evah I
noitcaer s’ydob ym tsniaga kcab thgif dna revihs I
.rehtona gniredro rehtob ot evah t’nod I won tsael tA
.noitceffa fo tib artxe elttil a tsuj ,em gnicrof ton
.denrub gnitteg fo diarfa flah m’I taht toh os dna
.ssenesolc sih fo htmraw eht
,em tsurT .dahC htiw tuo gnah ot ereh ni ylno s’eH“
.pu em gnitfil ,kcab ym rednu sedils smra sih fo enO
.gemtun htiw deppot
.thgin lla enohp ym ta gnirats knird on htiw ereh yats t’nac I ,ylraelC
etelpmoc s’thginot rof gnittes eht saw taht rab eht tsap thgiarts gniklaw tuohtiw emoh og t’nac I
,tnemtrapa na evah seod eh ,tuo snrut ti sA
.kcoc sih barg dna su neewteb hcaer I
,tsehc sih tsniaga nwod daeh ym worrub I
.thgin ykcul ym si thginot ebyaM
,enola gnittis s’eh dna erehwemos dehsinav evah sdneirf siH
,shtaerb peed wef a ekat I
htuom ni llits pit sih tsuj ,niaga kcab llup I
,mih ta erats
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.redrah gnitnap si su fo eno hcihw llet t’nac I
eviL“   yojne esaelP
.ecivda doog emos evah ll’eh tsael ta rO
,tnenitnoc rehtona no yllaretil eb lliw eH
repeed neve dees sih gnikrow
tsiaw sih dnuora smra nwo ym parw dluoc I
kciht eht ni eson ym gniyrub
,teknalb eht otni tlem em fo tser eht tel I
,lleW .noitullop thgil
.sdrawkcab espalloc I neht dna
,sehsulb yllautca eH
.rebbur ot seenk ym nrut ot snetaerht elims eht dna
”.uoy htiw yaw sih evah dna hcuoc eht revo uoy dneb ot mih tnaw uoy mih llet dna ,uort pord tsuJ“
.mih ssik ot tnaw I
.em otni stsurht drah ,gnol tub
hcum gniyas ton s’taht—
?I t’nera ,ereh flesym fo ssa etelpmoc a gnikam tsuj m’I
,god.ecioveht ta
,enim tsniaga pu gnisserp doohnam kciht sih gnileef enigami I
.em htiw ecnahc rehtona ekat ot gnilliw eb d’eh fi ees dna ,ezigolopa
.deb sih em wohs ot tnaw thgim dahC fi ees ot elddim ym dnuora lewot a parw dna elip a ni sehtolc ym evael I
.thgin a ni raf os hsup ylno nac I dna
.tfel d’uoy dezilaer eh sa noos sA“
”,ekaJ ,uoy teem ot eciN“
,uoy ni tseretni dewohs ydaerla eh ,eno ,lleW“
.elgnij sgnicreip sih raeh nac I raews I
?enim ot og ot tnaw ro ,ecalp sih ot kcab em ekat eh dluoW
.em sllet daeh ym ni miJ eht
,nosirroM ennA ylloH yb ”evoL rof eviL“
,gnimoc flesym dnif I taht taht retfa gnol ton s’tI
,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer
.elbatrofmoc dna tfos skool ti tub
,ti ekil t’nod uoy fI“
.em ta snirg dna seye sih snepo dahC
em ekaT“ .ffo mih tuc I
.spihsnoitaler gnolefil ,gnol-sedaced ,gnol-sraey
.seciohc efil ym etaulave I ,hgis a htiW
.lluf yletelpmoc ,yllufrednow os leef I
.notuf eht ffo steknalb fo kcats eht sbarg neht
.rewohs suoiruxul eht ot em swohs eh—
.si ti esruoc fo esuaceb
,llits sdloh eh sa flesmih gnirevihs
,yks eht ta pu yleugav gnirats
tsetorp ni gnikaeuqs rehtael eht raeh nac I
,nem lufituaeb htiw dellif ,yllatnedicni ,si hcihw
.riah sih fo sseniklis eht ta gnilevram
.peelsa llaf I litnu noisivelet thgin etal hctaw
,stuohs rednetrab eht ”!dahC !iO“
,nwal ynit a naht erom hcum ton
.ni kcab neht dna
.naeco eht fo weiv a htiw esir-hgih gib A
.edis evitcelloc ruo otno llor ot gnirevuenam emos sekat ti dna
gnirettahc era hteet siH
”.uoy rof kool og ot dediced dahC tub
,ylgnitnioppasid ,si eH
.sba draobhsaw sih tsniaga gnidils si kcid nwo ym dna
,dellifluf su fo rehtien ,tuo sllup eH
.srats eht ni tsol teg ot ysae s’ti
emos ot gniklat ereh s’eh dna
,htgnel sih no elzzum ym bob ot trats I
,teews dna kciht s’ti—pis a ekat I
.niaga yrt dna htaerb peed a ekat I
.sdrow otni tup ot ytiliba ym dnoyeb llew
.trihs ym gnikcutnu
,em dnuora snethgit mra siH
,em ta nwod gnirats si dna deppots sah dahC taht erawa emoceb I
,emit htneves ro htxis eht yB
,emoh em stnaw eh hcum woh em gnillet si yrreP evetS ,xobekuj eht nO
”,eituc ,ti knard uoy nehw edam uoy ecaf eht was I esuaceB“
elip eht hguorht segammur dna nac eh sa tseb sa pu stis dahC
,taht rednu soottat elbisivni ylraen
.ytic teiuq eht revo tuo erats ew sa
,tsiaw ym no sdnah sih
.kcab gnidlof morf srae ym peek ot gnilggurts ,knird ym ot ezag ym rewol ylitsah I
.htaerb ym hctac ot ecnahc a em evig ot kcab sllup dna
rewsna laer eht tuB
reppep dna tlas etiuq ton ,enam gnol A
,moor gnivil eht nI
.epacse erif eht ot em sdael eh neht dnA
.yeldutScM dahC sdrawot hcram dna ,sredluohs ym erauqs
.kaerb dniw larutan a etaerc xob renoitidnoc ria dna dehs eht dna
hcuoc sih no nwod spord eH
”,uoy rof gnikool saw dahC“
.egassem ym daer neve t’nsah miJ
.rae ym otni srumrum eh ”?ydaeR“
.daor eht nwod yltnalahcnon secnalg dna etteragic sih tuo sbuns eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.elzzum ym revo srettalps dnoces eht elihw
,notgnissatcefreP yldahC
,spihsnoitaler ruo ni ,elbisnopserri era ew taht noitasucca nommoc a si tI
,ereht stser tsuj tI
,relevart wollef ruoy
,em otni yteirbos emos skconk ria yllihc ehT
,dnim t’nod I ,ylknarF
”.emos esu dluoc uoy ekil kool uoy tub
os m’I“ .rednetrab eht ton ,tsipareht eht—
.rehtruf ni sregnif sih sgid dahC sa
,epacse erif eht pu mih wollof I .ti kcuF
.shtnom eerht rof gnivael s’eH .niaga yrt I
dahC tsap gnirats
,elims yhs a mih reffo I
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
.tcaf siht fo egatnavda lluf ekat ot flesym esimorp I dna
,liat ym rednu kcoc sih fo daeh eht sah kcidgnortS dahC—
steknalb dedlof yltaen fo elpuoc a sdloh oerets eht ot txen renroc eht ni notuf A
,kcen ym tsniaga daeh sih skcut dahC
.gnithgil mid s’rab eht ni remmihs dna
,ezeeuqs a sdnah ym sevig eH ”.od yllaer I
,yletelpmoc tuo sevig htgnerts yM
.sih no dnah ym ecalp ot egru eht tsiser I .dnik dna eltneg os sregnif sih
.pal sih ni gnittis m’I litnu pu em sllup neht
nosirroM .A ylloH yb ”evoL rof
,ylpeed gnirrup llits
”,yksihw rehtona uoy gnivres ton m’I“
.niaga pu siht wercs ot emit ,lleW ”.iH“ ”.iH“
,enola uoy tfel I rehtar d’uoy fI
.mih fo tser eht sa ytsat sa tsuj s’ti dna
.enim ni sdnah sih gnikat
.tehcorc ot gninrael trats neve t’nac I os ,sruoh rof nepo t’now erots ybboh eht dna
.sllab sih revo sesaet dna selkcit rehto eht elihw
?tenalp eht no nosrep gnitseretni tsom elgnis eht raeb eht si ro
,tuo denekcihc I tub
em fo pot no nwod syal dahC-yranigamI
”.wonk ot hguone emoh knuh enisru taht ekat ot deirt ev’I
,yks nepo eht rednu teknalb tfos a no nwod em yal ot
.drawrof detniop srae
”?ecivda doog uoy evig miJ diD“
,emit siht reisae si ni kcab gnihsuP
esruoc fo ,rehtael s’ti—
.flesym fo kcart tsol evah neve thgim I
.srae ym neewteb thgir ,daeh ym fo kcab eht no dnah a secalp dahC
.mM  .allinav fo hcuot a
,esroh eht sdrawot daeh sih sdon eH
.em gnirongi s’eh tub
.ekohc ylraen I dna
”.reknird eht saw eh ,xe ym ,llew
”.rewohs ruoy worrob thgim I hguohT“
,emit ot emit morf seod eno yaw eht ,gnileef eht teg I
,em ta worbeye na sesiar dahC .rumrum I
,edisa esle gnihtyreve ,wonk uoy os
,em ta yrgna teg t’ndluow miJ
.taorht ym nwod demmarc
.em fo edisni daol eht ot gnidda speek eh sa
,em htiw ti erahs ot reffo ot dessarrabme oot smees eh ,yldaS
worbeye na sesiar eH
.selim net nar tsuj ew ekil gnihtaerb era su fo htoB
.resolc elttil a em sezeeuqs eh ,esnopser nI
?revo gniloord saw eh raeb eht ton yhw ,tihS
.seod ti esruoc fo esuaceb ,tsiparehT gnihtooS eht miJ fo daetsni rednetraB decreiP eht miJ fo eciov deidobmesid eht serujnoc niarb yM .em llet dluow miJ tahw enigami ot yrt I
t’nod yllaer I tub ,taht evol d’I
shtnom eerht esoht rof tuoba kniht ot gnihtemos mih evig ot ytinutroppo eno ruoy si siht dna
kcurt-imes a fo htdiw dna htgnel eht ylhguor gnihtemos gnivah ot
.teknalb eht otni dekcut gnihtemos fo elttob a no gnidnal dnah ym
.mih tsniaga ni nael tsuj dna
,niaga em otni gnikcub si dahC
,secalP railim-ruF ni krow rehto reh eeS
”?lakcaj eht s’rednaX“
.ylper I ”,uoy knahT“
.thgin llaf eht otni gnimaercs nur ot stnaw em fo trap regral A
.morf tifeneb yllautca ot hguone ebibmi ot elba neeb t’nevah I
,rab eht fo edis raf eht ot sdaeh dna sdnats neht
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ereht ,msacras oN
uoy no rouqil doog gnitsaw ton m’I dnA“
,ti odrevo ot ton luferac eb ot evah I
.lewot etihw elttil a tub gnihton gniraew
,taht naht gnigru erom yna ekat t’nseod eH ”.emoh em ekat ,oS
wols dna ecin em otni skcub eh sa
,rehtruf yna sserp t’nseod eH
?ekil eb mih htiw enola thgin a dluow tahW
,ecreip ylefas dluoc uoy wonk t’ndid I secalp fo tol a ni sgnicreip dna
,ecneirepxe hcum evah t’nod I
,kcas sih revo regnif a nur I nehw spmuj eH
.epacse I sa rood eht raen kcar eht morf taoc ym gnibbarg
nosinu ni naom eW
!nosrep rehtona htiw evarc lla ew taht noitcennoc namuh ,peed taht teg oG !no oG“
eulb reicalg era seye siH
,enim tsniaga gnihsurb era spih sih emit eht yB
.stsixe worbeye na emussa I erehw edih taht latem fo tol a sesiar eh ,lleW
.pal sih otni pu em sllup eh dna
gnittink pu ekat nac I ebyaM
.tar eht morf don A
.redluohs sih no daeh ym tser ot ekil leef dluow ti tahw rednow I
.mih etsat tsomla nac I
”,irabaT dahC ,uoy teem ot desaelP“ ”.irabaT s’tI
,dehserfer ,naelc leef I ,rewohs eht retfA
ecaep tcefrep fo tnemom a s’erehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
:ssensuoiresnu ythgilf fo tuo ton si
.worbeye na sesiar tar ehT
.gnillortnoc ro evissessop ton ,gnitrofmoc
.etteragic evolc a gnikoms
.elims a gniyrt ,yas I ”,eruS“
wap ym sbarg eh nehT
,em no sdnah mraw ,gib sih leef ylraen nac I
,ksa I yhw wonk t’nod I .ksa I
s’ti dna ,ecaf evisserpxe yllaer a evah tsuj uoY“ .syas eh
mih ot tuo sdnah ym dloh I
,wohemos redrah neve gnitteg mih leef I raews I
.suoivbo oot gnieb morf meht pu gnipeerc hsulb eht tneverp ot kcab srae ym dlof I .toh leef I
,daeh ym ni dahC-yranigami eht syas
.htaerb a ekat ot kcab llup ot evah I erofeb
,ti yalp ot stnaw eh woh s’taht fi ,lleW
,rewsna thgim eno rO
,pmur ym ezeeuqs ot nwod spils sdnah sih fo enO
.elggig a sserppus I dna
.drah gnitteg mih leef nac I ,spih ym rednU
.daeh ym ni ysatnaf ythguan eht evah ll’I tsael ta
.ytnim era eugnot dna spil sih esuaceb
.cisum eht ot gnola daeh sih gniddon
.ti hcum ytterp s’tahT
miJ morf segassem wen nezod a s’erehT
,yadot gnihtemos od ot tnaw uoy fi dna
,dahC tpurretni ro
.gnihtemos fo elddim eht ni er’ew taht dahC dnimer ot spih ym kcor I .ma I oS
,ebul fo reniatnoc egral a s’tI
ytlas tib elttil a dna teews tub
,noitanigami ym ni eno eht naht nrow erom elttil a dna redlo s’tI
.dnim ym ni ralucsum erom neve
spih ralucsum sih revo kooh sgel ym litnu elggirw dna tfihs I
.kcid sih revo ebul gnibbur m’I neht dna
,pots dna wols ot emoc fo esoherif eht rof stnemom wef a sekat tI
.pu mraw ot uoy tnaw I oS“
.lufniap ton tub mrif si pirg sih
?tluciffid os siht si yhw ,hgU
,rotavele eht ni ffo sehtolc ruo pir t’nod eW
”evoL rof eviL“ saw sihT
.eunitnoc ot ydaer m’I taht langis ot
.uoy htiw emit erom dneps ot tnaw osla I
,ylthgils os reve detlit daeh
,pih eht ta denioj llits er’eW .sdeeccus yltsom
”?evol rof evil ew kniht t’nod uoY“ .dnim t’nod I
.lauxesomoh a er’uoy kniht thgim
.eb ot edam erew yeht woh dneirfyobdooG drawdahC llet ot strats dna rab eht no woble sih snael lakcaj ehT
,tsniaga nael ot elbatrofmocnu eb ot sa dilos os ton tub ,dilos s’eH
”,ti gnisu tuohtiw ereh pu yaw eht lla ti deirrac evah ot emahs a smees ti ,lleW“
.meht htiw yalp ot tnaw yllaer I dnA
niamer sgnileef taht sesimorp ehs sa tuo gnidaf si skciN eivetS ,oerets eht nO
,lakcaj gnikcuf taht s’ereht dnA
.drawkwa ylneddus ,syas eh ”,hA“
.rebos ylgnisserped dna ,detcejed ,dloc
?taht htiw gnorw s’tahw dna
,sehtolc sih fo tser eht dehs ot dahC rof gnol ekat t’nseod tI
,serots desolc fo kcolb a tsap
.ti etaicerppa ot gniog ton er’uoy fi
,ti ees I yaw ehT
,keehc ym fo ruf eht otni gnikaos yltnatsni
.kcab nworht daeh
.rab eht otni kcab gniraeppasid erofeb kniw a em sevig neht
,enalp eucser a nwod gniggalf s’eh ekil smra htob sevaw tar eht dna pu skool dahC
enodnu stnap sih teg I
.steehs klis sah ti teb I
,klim etalocohc a ekil
.kcab srae dna nwod daeh
yub ot woh wonk elpoep hcir ylno taht spopillol terces esoht ekil s’eH
,aes eht ni hsif fo ytnelp
”.ffo koot uoy tespu yllaer demees eh tub
,gnol a tuo tel dna
.gnicrof reven ,gnihsur reven
.reverof ereh tis t’nac I dna ,ytpme si knird yM
,hcuoc rehtael eht no tuo dehcterts ,dahC-yranigami s’erehT
.em dnuora mra taht dah eh hsiw I
,rednaX morf epacse ot etunim a mih koot tI
.gurhs a htiw sdda rednetrab eht ”,rehtorb detpodA“
,emit dnoces eht rof
”.lliw esle enoemos ,won tohs ruoy ekat t’nod uoy fI
,gnihtemos ro mug emos dah evah tsum eH
.yats ot mih ksa ot tnaw I
.xes yug-elcsum toh evah ot tesnus eht otni ffo piks ,dekan kcub ,meht fo owt eht
.won gnihtyna naht wolley erom skool knird rebma elap eht dna detlem lla sah eci ehT
,elttil a tsuj ,nwod em pid d’eH
”.eman eht htiw seog tI
.ti barg dna og ot deen uoy
.dahC ta worbeye na esiar I
.htuom ym otni pit tnulb sih ekat ot deen I tnemegaruocne eht lla s’tahT .naom yppah a dna
,em fo edisni yaw eht lla sesserp eh sa
.rab eht nwod yaw ym gnikam trats dna egaruoc ym lla pu wercs I
.noitanigami ynroh ym ni ecalp on sah scisyhP
.oediv cisum htog a fo tuo thgiarts emac eh ekil s’tI
,aera eht ni sgnidliub rehto eht fo yna naht rehgih si tnemtrapa siH
”?bocaJ“ ”?sruoy s’tahW“
.eltneg os smees eh tub ,yug gib a s’eH
.hsaw-ydob erotsgurd ekil yletomer ton dna
,pal elbatrofmoc yrev
.latsyrc ekil er’yehT
.nwod rehtruf neve elzzum ym gnihsup no krow I elihw taht ydemer I dna
.emit siht worbeye na esiar I
.em rof tsrow eht eb dluow enola gnittis taht
,erofeb tlef reve ev’I gnihton ekil s’tI
,tuo sllup eh erofeb shgiht
,krap elttil a ta flesym dnif I litnu
.thginot erehwyna em nettog t’nsah em ot teg yteixna ym gnittel ,sediseB
,eton thgim I ,si hcihw—em gnissik enod s’eh nehW
,taes sih ni drawrof gninael
.ynroh ytterp llits dna
.tnasaelpnu ton s’ti tub
spih ym otno gnidloh si dahC ,maerdyad ym nI
.elbissop yaw tseb eht ni taht naem I dna
.nihc sih rednu revlis nrut ot gnitrats riah kcalb hcir htiw—
.trihs-t llams-oot-ezis-eno-ebyam
,eituc ,meetse-fles emos teg ot deen uoy ,owT
.tnemtrapa sih fo kcab eht sdrawot em sdael dna
?mih ot gniklat tsuj erew uoY“
.rednetrab eht syas ”,hA“
,rab eht fo dne raf eht ot gnireev flesym dnif I dna em sdrawot nrut ot strats eH
.detnorffa eb ot gnidneterp ,ksa I ”?ton yhW“
.yks eht ta pu kool dna sehcneb eht fo eno no nwod polp I
.erom yna klat nac I kniht t’nod I—don I
.ynnuf em ta nwod skool dna spots dahC ,ysatnaf ym nI
.redluohs sih revo nworht s’eh snaej eht fo tuo syek sih selbmuf dahC sa
.ylleb ym fo ruf tfos eht tsniaga gnibbur
,noitanigami ym fo dlrow gnisaelp erom hcum eht ni kcaB
”,ezilaer t’ndid I dna tnelis no saw enohp ym ,bocaJ ,yrros
,em otni hcni yb hcni flesmih gnikrow ,wols seog eH
,wollahs era ew taht
,noillats ym gnitaorhtpeed no desucof saw I elihw llits enog evah sdnah yM
.tfahs sih htiw gniyalp gniyojne m’I sa hcum sa
.doog os etsat dluoc yug a wonk t’ndid I .rovalf ytiurf
esu elpoep taht rennam dnahffo
.staeper elcyc eht neht dna
:tnempiuqe sih htiw dliw seog noitanigami yM
.hcuoc eht no nwod spolf eh sa sksa ydobdooG trebdahC ”?ti ekiL“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.deuqip ,yas yeht sa ,si tseretni ym tub
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sdaeh ruo evoba srats thgirb fo esnapxe eht dna em dnuora dna
,aval netlom fo lluf depmup gnieb m’I ekil s’tI
,nwod dna pu mih ekorts ot trats I
,redrah ,rehguor gnimoceb si htaerb siH
,rab eht ta desu eh nirg emas eht s’tI
.emoh og ot tnaw t’nod I
.esle gnihtyna htrow si ,hguoht ,weiv ehT
.dees sih htiw em gnilif mih leef nac I neht dna
,evitnetta os s’eH
.tuo larips ot tnaw t’nod I
.teef wef a nihtiw sward eh sa tlah a ot gniddiks
,maerdyad ym s’tI .oN
enohp ym ta ecnalg
htiw tar ynwarcs a ,rednetrab ehT
.noitcaer lanoitome eguh a gnitcepxe er’yeht nehw
,rewsna thgim eno hcihw oT
,klaw eht no hcum klat t’nod eW
sevooh ,em ot—snur yllautca—snur dahC
?taht fo nuf eht eb dluow tahw tub ,thgin
,ti welb I !kcuF .kcuf kcuf kcuF
,mraw siht leef dluoc I wenk reven I
sa kniw a em sevig revird bac ehT .sseltrihs m’I
.tfel eht ot si esuoh yM
,eson eht no elttil A
,htaehs sih fo tuo gnikop ,kcoc drah-flah sih
,og ot mih llet ot tnaw I .gnihtyna
,srehto eht ta ecnalg I .sdaer ti
,evissam yletulosba si
.knird s’dik a ton yletinifed s’ti hguoht
.nac I sa tseb sa sgel ym ssorc dna nwod reknuh I
,em ot repsihw ot rab eht ssorca gninael ,syas tar eht
”.won si eh ereht ,kool ,hO“
.em fo edisni s’eh neht dna
.lohocla eht s’taht ebyam rO
dna cigam sih skrow tub
.miJ ot egassem kciuq a toohs dna tekcop ym fo tuo enohp ym pils neht
.enilno nray emos redro ll’I
sih etacav ot gnivah tuohtiw su neewteb sdnah ym teg ot hguone tfihs ot drawkwa elttil a s’tI
.sdrow fo tuo nur ev’I dnif neht tub
,ssik a ni tsol si troter yM
,enog d’uoy erehw wenk eno oN“
.dahC no sthgila ezag yM
.selims dna eye ym sehctac dahC .pu dnats dna
.leef I sa drawkwa sa skool eH
,gniodnu trats I erofeb steknalb eht fo tuo yaw nwo sti sdnif lewot yM
,sseldrageR
kcil elttil a kcoc sih fo daeh eht evig I
.gnihtolc no-yarps nwonknu erofotereh a ro stnap rehtael tsethgit s’dlrow eht rehtie si tahw ni
,enim otni spih sih gnikcor si dahC
.mih dnuora skcol sgel ym peek ot htgnerts ym fo lla sekat ti dna
,nosirroM .A ylloH yb
.ssik rehtona tey em evig ot dnopser nac I erofeb pu sgnirps eH .sksa eh
,evitcartta yllaer er’uoy kniht I“
,seye laicalg lufituaeb sih otni pu kool dna mih fo tnorf ni nwod leenk I
,tuo raelc dna dloc s’tI
htuom ym otni erp gnikael s’eH
”.dahC ta seye oom gnikam uoy ees nac I“
egaruoc diuqil fo ssalg a htiw renroc eht ni gnidih xnyl thgiew egareva-erom-eb-dluoc ,thgieh egareva
.elttil a sgurhs dna
.sseug I ,sexnyl dna ecim fo snalp dial tseb tub
sredluohs daorb ot stcennoc taht kcen ralucsum ,gnol a semarf ,dediarb yltaen ,eb lliw ti tub
,hcum knird t’nod uoY
xe ym ekil gnitsat mih enigami ot decrof m’I dna
.pu em sevaw dna rediw snirg tsuj eh tub
,yltnerappa ,I esuaceb
.kazum rotavele yb dedrabmob gnieb ekil s’tI .rehtona dna
sllab evitisnes hcus htiw yug a tem reven evah I
.seye eulb-eci esoht otni gnirats m’I .ssefnoc I ”,on ,hA“
,ruf elap sih otni deyd sngised cirtemoeg luftra
.seye sih teem ot
,erofeb enoyna detaorhtpeed reven ev’I
,rehtona neht dnA
.aluvu ym tsniaga spmub eh litnu
tuo gniralb ,xobekuj eht fo dnuos eht revo mih raeh t’nac I
,nosaer revetahw roF
”,suovren uoy gnikam m’I fI“
.ssensuoires evarg fo tuo si ti
,syas eh ”,dahC m’I“
,mraerof eht no em sehcuot eH
.ecnartne ym tsniaga sesserp pit sih sa
?taht htiw gnorw s’tahw :niaga dna
.niaga knird ym gnieye flesym dnif I
.erus m’I ,od ot tahw wonk ll’eH
,sthgilteerts eht evoba ,ereh pU
.sseug ot drah ton
.niaga ecno em tsniaga spih sih gnikrow
,kcab ym fo llams eht no ruf eht hguorht yalp sregnif siH
”?esle gnihtemos uoy wohs dluoc I
.xobekuj eht raen
.ffo tfel I erehw pu kcip ot yrt dna seye ym esolc I
,syas dna em ta selims eH
.ti kcehc dna tuo enohp ym llup I
.liat sih evoba tsuj dekcol selkna
.elzzum ym otni teg t’nac I tahw dnuora dnah ym parw I
,stnap fo kcal ym sdrawot don lufgninaem a dna
”,gnizeerf er’uoY“ ”?tahW“ ”.emoh
.em ta ecnuob kcoc evissam sih gnikam
,hctorc sih ni elzzum ym gniyrub fo secnahc ym fo luftbuod m’I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ecaf ym pu gnipeerc hsulf a leef I ”!hO“
paehc taht ton dnA
,won siht eganam t’nod I fI
,hguoc em sekam dna taorht ym snrub tI
ot kcab llup I .noitatiseh on yletulosba htiw syas eh ”,kcidnortS“
.nac eh sa ylthgit sa em ot flesmih gnisserp s’eh neht dna
?miJ wonk eh seod lleh eht woH
.htnom eht rof ssenevitressa fo tnemtolla ym pu desu ev’I esuaceb doog si hcihw
.lla mih ekat neve nac I gnizama m’I taht
.oerets eht htiw gnola gnimmuh
.hcuoc rehtael a evah seod yllaer eh dna
?eugra ot I ma ohw tub
tsehc sih no daeh ym gnitser flesym dnif I dna
.ecalp sih ot em ekat tsuj dluohs eh dna
.noitanigami nwo ym yb dekcolbkcoC .tihS
,kniw a em sevig eH
,hcuoc eht no tis ,emoh og tsuJ
,tuo emoc sdrow on
.flesym egatobas ot tnaw yllaer
,dleifelttaB A sI evoL
.em rof enohpllec ym seveirter dna tekcop a otni sehcaer eH
”?eman tsal ruoy s’tahw ,yeh ,ha
.pit sih revo eugnot hguor ym nur hguone kcab llup I sa sehtaerb dahC ”,yekaJ ,dog ,hO“
.yldaorb gninnirg llits
.elbaresim erom neve leef em ekam si seod taht lla tub
,hsup a regnol ton s’ti
”?miJ si eman sih ,rednetrab ehT
.ebul deen t’nseod em-yranigami gniht doog a s’tI
ffo raf oot t’nsaw noitanigami ym taht llet nac I
.ti puc I nehw slaeuqs yllautca neht
,efil laer ni siht ekil yrev gnihtemos dah evah dluoc I taht em dnimer ot ysatnaf ym stpurretni niarb yM
,steknalb eht fo elpuoc a nwod syal dahC
dna htuom ym nepo I
,ssenwols gnihca emas taht htiW
”.tnaw I sgniht eht rof ksa ot woh nrael ot gniyrt llits m’I dnA“ .ssefnoc I
,em yb yako s’taht dna
,repsihw a fo noitamixorppa doog a tsael ta ro
.hcamots drah-kcor sih tsniaga gnipmub si noitcere nwo yM
”?ereh tis I fi dnim ,iH“
.tnaw I revetahw ekil etsat nac eh
.war elttil a sleef eciov ym tub
.siht ot desu teg dluoc yug A
.ruf ym otni yaw rieht gnikrow ylwols sregnif esoht
,kcid esroh fo niatnuom siht gnikat elbuort on evah I
”.rehtorb thgiarts sih si raeb taht ,eerhT
,tsurht tsal eno htiw sehsinif eh sa sedis sih ot gnippord sgel ym
.fo tros ,dneirf a s’eH .on ,haey ,hO“
.em fo edisni s’eh neht dna
.em yhW“ .taeper I ”?yhW“
,ezeeuqs elttil a wap ym sevig eH
,gnihtemos yas ot tnaw I ”.drow eht yas tsuj
,ecarbme sih dna pal sih otni gnibmilc maerdyad I
,daeh ym fo kcab eht no dnah sih stser dna
.rehtie ,yrrehc enicidem hguoc
.daehelbbob a s’eh ekil raeb eht ta gniddon
.ecnuob ot em esuac ot hguone drah em otni smals eh ,trons a htiW
”,pihsnoitaler dab yllaer a fo tuo tog tsuj I“
.saw ti naht redloc hcum ylneddus s’taht teknalb a no em gnivael ,sdnats dna
,loord fo tnuoma gnissarrabme na yb dedia
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
”.ni tuc I fi dnim t’nod uoy epoH“
.melborp a ton s’ti ,dahC-yranigami rof tub
”?tahW“ ”?yhW“ ”.revetahw
.steknalb eht otni kcab em syal eh sa em sessik eH
,drah gniwolb si dahC roop ees ot drawpu ecnalg I
,renetsil taerg a tsuj eh sI
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
a rednu scep denifed-llew dna
.niaga ecnahc eht teg reven thgim I
ni dahC fo gnileef eht otni nwod sedaf ecnetsixe fo llA
.steknalb eht ni erehwemos morf emihc lacisum egnarts a s’ereht nehw elgguns tsuj ot ydaer ma dna
”—tub hcum oot sgniht gnihsup
sih senilcni rednetrab ehT
.otohp tra fo tros emos ekil
gnillaf morf em gnipeek smra ralucsum
.emit fo kcart esol I
.noitcere eguh a htiw thgin ta hcneb krap a no gnittis
.ereht maerdyad taht tfel dah I taht togrof I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”,emosdnah ,tnaw uoy revetahW“
.ta erats ot esle gnihtemos rof gnikool rab eht tuoba tsac dna
.esion prrm yratnulovni elttil a evig em ekam ot hguone drah
,ot denut oidar eht tog s’eh noitats gninetsil ysae eht pu snrut revird bac eht
,mih ta pu kool ot egaruoc ym lla sekat tI
.ecarbme sih ni yllej enilef fo llab gnireviuq a naht erom elttil m’I
mih gnissik enod m’I erofeb llew
,era seye sih lufituaeb woh ees nac I ecnatsid siht ta nevE
”,ti tuoba yrrow t’noD“
”,eivetS ,ti tog uoY“
,thgir ton s’taht ,oN
,bac a su erih dluow eH .ediced I ,siH
.cisum eht gniredisnoc
”,yllaer ,dahC ,seY“ ?yllaeR
.taoc ym ,gniretne retfa yltrohs yrev ,dna
,)?uoy era erehw ,miJ ,timmad ,segassem on(
.su revo gnilkniwt srats thgirb
,emac I yaw eht kcab egdurt I sa flesti slaever nalp ym ni walf ehT
.liat ym rednu ti ediug ot tfahs sih ekat dna nwod hcaer I
seirots tluda ekopseb gnireffo
.evohs elttil a em sevig eH
.tnemtrapa yranigami s’dahC yranigami ni em yranigami eht naem t’nod I dna ,drah
,yawa kcolb a tuoba klawedis eht nwod gnilffuhs si esroh gib ehT
.nrecnoc sih ees ot etuc ytterp si ti tub
elpoep ta doog on m’I mih llet ot detpmet si em fo traP
,emoh klaw dluoc I .kcots ekat I
!sdnim daer nac eh ,tihS .syas eh
,ecaf eht ni erauqs em stih tohs tsrif ehT
,edis siht no tsael ta
.elbat eht ssorca mih ecnuop ot egru eht tsiser I
,egassem eht steg ydob ym ,yrt driht eht nO
elddim sih dnuora shgiht ym ezeeuqs em rof gnitiaw
.thguoht eht ta hteet ym tirg I
”,ecnetsixe ni renetsil tseb eht eb ll’I ,nettik ,uoy roF“
,tsiaw sih dnuora sgel ym parw yltneidebo I dna
,nedrag elttil a pu tes sah enoemoS
”,onnud I“ .yawa hcni eno tsuj si evol taht gnisimorp si regnis ehT
.yas I ”,gnizama s’tI“
.leef ot sehcni fo tol a era ereht dna
kciht ylbidercni os s’eH
,rab eht fo dne rehto eht sdrawot daeh decreip-llew
.ydaerla em ot esolc oot s’eH
yehT .yug a no nwod gniog tuoba gnizisatnaf er’uoy wonk rab yag eht ni enoyna tel t’nac ,yekaJ ,luferaC
.dnah sih em sreffo eH
,etsah ruo taht si
,noitanigami ym eb thgim tI .mih llet I
,gniog peek ,yb no evoM
”.htiw elbatrofmoc ton er’uoy gnihtyna otni uoy hsup ot tnaw
.taoc ym tuo sllup eh litnu
.ssalg elohw eht nwod neht dna
esroH eht selcsuM morf noitnetta emos evah ot evol dluow ohw syug regae fo lluf rab elohw A
.rehtael tsomla gnihtemos fo enotrednu na htiw larolf yltniaf
.ediw daerps sgel—
,esraps elttil a fi ,ecin si tnemtrapa siH
,ylgnitivni spih sih kcub dna kniw mih enigami I
.enohp ym kcehc I  .kcots emoS
.kcen tnagele sih dnuora gnipard smra ym
,liatkcoc ym fo tser eht nwod
,erised esab yb ylno detavitom
,mih fo lla ekat ot gnitnaw
,yub nac yenom hsaw ydob ercoidem ylevissergga tsom eht fo stnanmer eht rednu
,pu s’tahw mih ksa I
.flesruoy hctac doog ytterp a er’uoy
.nemodba drah-kcor sih snioj htaehs sih erehw ruf fo hsub
.raeb eht htiw tnemugra detaeh a ni won
.flesym gninaom diova ot eugnot ym etib I ,dlrow laer eht nI
.ssik eht kaerb ot gnivah tuohtiw seenk sih dnuora nwod dna
”,retal ti htiw laed ll’I“
,naelc os sllems eH .esolc ni nael I
.noihsuc eht gnihcnelc dnah
.mih ta daeh ym kcoc dna knird ym pis I
,reve sa eltneg sa tsuj sniamer dnah rehto siH
,elbram morf devrac saw ti ekil skool taht ssa na fo weiv tnellecxe
.rab eht ni toof pets ot egaruoc eht pu dekrow I erofeb deb ot tnew ylbaborp eH
.enips ym pu elkcit
”,era uoy erehT“ .esolc emoc I sa—
elzzum ym no yldriew stis tI
,ti tuoba retteb kniht nac I erofeB
.sdnah sih ta nwod gnikool
.hguE .pis tnatiseh a ekat I
.mih gnigaruocne ,mih tsniaga kcub ot tseb ym od I dna
,tnemom a rof mih hctaw dna
”?saw eH“ .pots I
.smaerd ym ni kcab yal ot em gnigaruocne si oerets ehT
.ssalg a tuo gnillup ,syas eh
.roolf sih no tuo teg ew sa dekan htob er’ew taht desirprus yldlim m’I dna
.nosirp yklis sti morf kcoc sih eerf ot srexob sih otni wap a kcits I nehw
.das si elims siH
,hcuoc rehtael eht ssorca gnulf si mra enO
.remrahC eniuqE eht
.ria eht ni stsorf htaerb yM .thgis teiuq
.seye laicalg suoegrog esoht htiw kool rehtih-emoc ylevol taht em gnivig ,yalpsid lluf no
.edolpxe ot gniog s’ti yrrow I drah os gnitaeb si traeh yM
…yas ot htuom ym nepo I dna ,gninnirg llits
”.netfo yrev thginot nwod teg ot evah ot tcepxe“
.nruter ni kaeuqs elttil a mih evig I dna
.htuom ym otni mih fo noitrop doog a teg nac I tuB
.ti yojne tsuj yllaer I
.su neewteb selddaw-turts soreconihr a ekil tliub lakcaj a
.em morf ssorca taes eht otni gnippord ,syas eh
.em htiw flesruoy rehtob ot deen t’nod uoy
esoht fo erom tuo ward ot gnitnaw
,esolc em gnillup dna elddim ym dnuora gnidils smra sih ,syas dahC
…tsuj I“ .timda I ”,oN“ ”?uoy od
”,dnim ruoy daer t’nac I ,oN“
sih fo ffo ecnuob em gnikam
.tuo larips ot ton si gniht tnatropmi eht ,yakO
.evah ew emit suoicerp tahw etsaw ot gnisufer era eW
,htaerb peed a ekat I
.sredluohs ym dnuora mra na pils seod eh tub
?pu em tahc ot gniyrt gniod eh s’tahW
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,rab siht ni yug tseixes eht si dahC
eh dna ,em no espalloc ot ton tseb sih seod dahC
”,ot uoy sllet cisum ym revetahw od ot gniog er’uoy fI“  ”.dnim reven ,yrroS“
.tnemegaruocne hcum ekat t’nseod tI
.nezorf-flah skool yug rooP
ysatnaf ym ni elbmaerp on s’erehT
”,worromot retfa yad eht gnivael s’eH“
.syas eh ”,dnatsrednu I“
.htuom ym erolpxe eugnot sih tel I dna ssik eW
.tsrif ,ssik ecreif a otni em sllup eH
.yekaJ ,htaerb peeD
.sedaf rettilg eht nehw neve
erusaelp fo naom gnol a tuo tel dna kcab daeh ym worht I maerdyad eht nI
?eugra ot I ma ohw
eerht ot tnuoc I
.tnorfretaw eht naht retnec ytic ot resolc s’ti tub
,repeerc a m’I sgniht yb gnissap eno on os osla
noos tub ,dnuora dnah ym parw ot em rof gib oot tsomla s’tI
,em ta gninnirg ,on—gnilims s’eH
ecnatsbus deroloc-eeffoc ,suoiretsym a htiw em stneserp
”,eituc ,drawkwa ti gnikam er’uoy esuaceb drawkwa ylno s’tI“
.dnats dna hgis a tuo tel I
.redduhs ot mih gnisuac
,sdrow ekam flesym ekam t’nac llits I
.ni kcab elgguns dna steknalb eht otno enohp eht ssot neht
.em ta worbeye na sesiar
,dahC syas ”,kool ,hA“ .lufpleH
.enim ot spil sih sesserp eh sa
,mraw si dnah siH .ekahs eW
,noitanigami ym nI
,dial teg ot detnaw I
lla ti erimda dna ereh tis dluoc I .evissam s’eH
.rab siht ni esle enoyna yllaretil ton yhW
,hcuoc eht no tuo dehcterts si selcsuMcaM kciwdahC
.em sessik dahC sa spsag dna snaom tfos eht tuo nword ot
.gnihtemos ro ,srotnevni taerg fo seutats fo elpuoc a dna ,sehcneb emos
.ssenilenol fo efil a ot flesym ngiser dna emoh og llew sa thgim I ,tihS
.ekorts yreve no etartsorp ym revo gnidilg si kcoc tnulb sih ylneddus neht dna
.stnap sih gniraew llits
gninnalp elbisnopser ,rebos ,luferac fo kcal tnerappa ruo
…dahC ,gnineve na etiuq neeb sah sihT“
.gnikam s’eh sdnuos lufrednow
.citnaig oot tsuj s’eh
,mih ot esolc em gnillup
”!oohS !dial teg tsael ta rO
fo wolg mid eht tsap elbisiv era srats tahw dna em tsuj s’ti os
.eson ym hguorht shtaerb peed lareves ekat I sa
,daeh ym nI  .tcefreP
.tib a erolpxe I elihw reyalp drocer ssendoog-ot-tsenoh eht htiw flesmih seisub neht dna tnemtrapa sih otni su stel eH
.smsagro dahC erofeb dnoces tilps a ekatsim ym ezingocer I
.sllab sih eldnof ot nwod sehcaer dnah eerf ym elihw
ro noitazinilased naht rehto
.detsaw si dees suoicerp taht fo erom erofeb htuom ym ni kcab mih teg I
,desolc rethgit elttil a taoc ym llup I
naom evitaicerppa na sevig eH
.eugnot ym htiw edisrednu sti gnippuc
?thgir ,dneirfyob a sa mraw sa tuoba s’teknalb a—
”.ecalp siht tog I yhw s’tahT“
,si taht ,em laer eht ,I
.uoy gnisaet tsuJ“ .shgual dahC
,hcneb ym no kcab nael I ,dlrow laer eht nI
pal sih ffo ylidob em stfil dna ssik eht skaerb eH
.ecneconni tcefrep htiw yas I
.noitalupop gninrecsid eht ot
,leets revo ynitas s’eH
.ydob regae dna gnilliw s’dahC gnirolpxe ylbaborp si lakcaj esuoh-kcirb emos won dna
taht ni syas eh
,yllacinahcem tfahs sih gnikorts si wap eno ,elihw eht llA
,em otni gnidils mih fo hcni yreve leef nac I
.foor eht ot yaw eht lla seog epacse eht
.mih fo tnorf ni nwod gnileenk flesym enigami I
.xes lausac dna sgnilf paehc otni hsur ew taht
.nosaer a rof rab siht ni gnittis m’I taht em dnimer dluow eh tub
.tsehc nwo ym hcuot I ”.gnirrup er’uoY“
.htiw yalp ot sdnah htob ekat thgim yeht ekil skool sllab sih elihw
.era uoy fi yrt a ti evig ot gnilliw s’eh
,suoiciled popillol-elpoep-hcir toN .suoiciled s’eH
eno siht piks esaelp
”.thginot ecivda tseb eht em nevig ton sah rataneB taP“ ,yas I
.sdnah fo tol a sekahs ohw yug a si sihT
.yaw flah tuoba tuo flesmih llup eh
.kcab sih dniheb selkna ym ssorc I neht dna
.yaj eulb a dna raeb a neewteb loots a otno gnilttes
,riahc sih ni dnuora deleviws sah dahC
.drawrof seye ym peek ot noitartnecnoc ym fo lla sekat tI
,noitanimreted elttil a htiw tub
,setunim wef tsap eht revo rethgit yltnacifingis nettog evah snaej ym taht seciton eno on epoh dna ereh fo tuo kaens ot era snoitpo ym
,oga sruoh tes ydaerla dah noom fo revils elttil ehT
.gnihtemos tuoba gnilkcac er’yeht dna yaj eulb eht dnuora mra na tog s’eH
,niaga neht dna ,stsurht neewteb elttil a stfihs eH
ti no decnalab emocerp fo pord ylraep a sah daeh eniuqe ,tnulb ehT
”.esle enoemos tuoba gniklat erew uoy thguoht I ,yrroS“