.gnihton ,pleh rof gnillac on s’ereht ,tihs gnikniht m’I
kcuts s’eh esuaceb gniwolleb mih era sesion txen ehT
.tsaeb sselhtrow siht rof toN
.esuoh eht edisni morf dnuos
.etal oot m’I tub ,tuohs I ”!ti hcuot t’nod ,oN“
,devresbo ylevitca gnieb er’yeht ekil leef yeht sa noos sA
,niaga em ta gnirats s’eh dna
ygoloozotpyrC ni SB a tog ev’I dna ,oot ,thguoht I tahw s’taht ,em eveileB
.wonk t’nod I .gnihtemos ro skcitsdray ro selacs dna saremac htiw tuoba gnimoc eb lliw sseug I ohw ,srehcraeser suolupurcsnu ffo eracs dna
.gnihtemos ro doof sih tuoba ybbarc steg saisetC sselnu
.flesym ffo sdnah ym peek ylerab nac I ,os ro keew txen eht rof dna edisni kcab nur I dna
,ihsus ,nekcihc deirf
”.neppah ti sekam eh dna ,gnihtemos ro yag er’yeht kniht ew esuaceb yag era snrocinu skniht eh kniht I …kniht I
.ssorg repus s’ti dna ,erehwyreve tihs snrocinU .a2
”.esolc oot teg t’noD“
.meht fo yna ta toohs yllautca d’I ekil toN
.stsixe nwod dna pu sraews enoyreve hcihw snrocinu efil laer lautca eht tuoba tuo gnimoc noitamrofni on yllacitcarp s’ereht ,elihwnaeM
!em ot deneppah tsuj ti ,esohc I gnihtemos t’nsi sihT
,semit elpuoc a mih tem ylno ev’I .dad s’akuY s’tI ”.yob ,ysaE“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
nrobbuts em sllac ehs nehT
nrocinu  a htiw tcatnoc otni gnimoc ,eeS
,deirram s’ehs kniht I
.syddaD raguS htiw rehtegot kcuts era swaj sti esuaceb deifirret eno nees ev’uoy retfa laeppa citnamor rieht fo tol a esol snrocinU
.drawkcab sllaf dna oop nrocinu raelc fo
elttil a gnikahs strats dna tespu yllaer steg ehs nehT
,ereh si syawla tI
.thgil fo dlrow a otni gninepo depahs-esroh a ekil
,yad yreve ylraen
”?sgniht denialpxe ehS“
.eromyna draeb eht ees t’nac eh taht won trohs pu sward
.ria eht ni cra na gnikam ,sevooh sti morf sliart thgil derolocitluM
.elbuort ni erew uoy deracs tog I sseug I dna ,gniod erew uoy
?yas ot desoppus I saw tahw tub ,eil bmud a saw ti os ,yakO
nrocinu eht htiw tcatnoc ni gnimoc morf su peek ot desoppus s’taht gniht ydob-lluf ,yvaeh ,gib a—
”?yawa og ti seod nehw
.rehtie gniyl eb t’now I
.ti teg I won dna
.deneppah taht esle gnihtyreve erofeb neve ,emit eht ta did dna
tahW“ .ni gnisserp
tsrif tius drazah ym otni gnitteg tuoba kniht tsael ta ot desu I
”?ereh reh gnirb uoy did yhW ?tahw did uoY“
,oga shtnom tuo ti derugif I esuaceB
htuom ruoy ni wobniar teg ot taerg ton ylbaborp—
,llih a nwod ti ssot dna esuoh eht dnuora wobniar eht trac ew sa si siht gnizama lla woh tuoba em ot erom selbbab ehS
,enod reve ev’I sgniht lufwa eht lla otni thgiarts gnikool eb tsum ti kniht I dna em ta serats tI
”—eht fo luferac eb ,yeH“
:gnivah sa meht debircsed eh taht
,keew a semit elpuoc A
,doohdlihc ym morf sgnos dlo
,etalocohc dna sregrubmah gnidnamed erew yeht ,yad a tuoba nihtiW
.mih retfa llih eht pu strats ehs dna
.xineohP ni scisyhpateM fo ytisrevinU lanoitanretnI ,sknahT
,htrof dna kcab gnittort dna gniknow ,tuo gnikaerf si saisetC
.2   .sgniht diputS
?siht detnaw I kniht uoY“
.dloc-eci seog ehS
.reh morf yawa sdnuob dna srekcin nrocinu ehT
.nruter ot desirprus oot m’I
,llew—gniod nemow fo sthguoht htiw pu sllif daeh yM
?uoy t’ndid ,em morf yawa teg ot ereh tuo emac uoY“   .gurhs I
:snrocinu tuoba uoy rof tcaf sunob a s’erehT
”.em dewollof evah tsum eH
.em ta wollip ym sworht ehs dna
”,taht tuoba yrros ,haeY“   ”?taht saw tahw—
.em ta serats ehS
?rebmemer ,ygoloozotpyrc ni eergeD
…s'raob dliw a ekil daeh a…“
.hguoht ,lufetarg ton s’eH
”.revo yaw eht no gnihtyreve denialpxe ehS“ .syas akuY
neeb t’nevah yeht erehw ot raeppasid nac yeht ecalp on eb lliw erehT
”?wollip ruoy rednu nrop yag ereht si yhw“
,sbbe fo dnik taht elihw a retfA
?taht tuoba ynnuf gnikcuf os s’tahW
,skool suordnow ,gnol eseht em gnivig speek eH
ti od nac uoy tuo erugif uoy retfa syad wef tsrif esoht rebmemer uoY
.derewol nroh ,gniglub seye sih
,niarb dezis-tunlaw s’saisetC ni dnA
.ti ekil t’nseod saisetC esuaceb gnineppah morf taht peek ot yrt I tub
.yawa ecnatsid elttil a stort dna yllacisum straf saisetC
redluohs ym revo kcab kool I
.drocer lissof eht ni ecart orez evael dna
,llaw eht ni peed dna doog degdew s’nroh siH
.oga shtnom eerht tuoba detrats tI“
.ffo em sessip fo dnik hcihw ,em ta sreggins tsuj eH
!pahw a s’ereht dna
.RCV/VT dlo na dna egdirf a htiw ,mrod egelloc a fo ezis eht tuoba si hcihw ,esuoh elttil eht em swohs
ti gnidir tuoba gnimaerd ylbaborP
.mrala eht ffo tes t’nseod taht eno
reduol yaw dnuos ti sekam taht ekarb elzzum a tog s’elfir ehT
snrocinU tuobA stcaF elbaveilebnU 6“
,ylraen ,ylraen dnA
,raelc tsaoc ,wohynA .retal nialpxe ll’I .lamina diputs siht gnitcetorp
.owt ro tohs gninraw a erif ll’I
.gnihtyreve ot srewsna drow-owt reh htiw tahw ,raf og t’nod irtuP htiw noitasrevnoc pu trats ot stpmettA
.ssorg t’nera sehtolc ym erus ekam dna
.nwod em gnillup er’uoy tahT“
m’I taht erus rof wonk lliw enoyreve
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
s’ereht dna ,seohs ym ta gnihcleuqs dna trid naht retaw erom gnidloh si dnuorg eht
,krow rof gnilevart eno eht saw I won taht dam ytterp saw ehs kniht I
.suoires laer steg eerged tihsllub ym
.teef reh ot flah gnitteg ,elap enog s’ehS
?snrocinu ,si gniht eht ,eeS“ .yas I
.hcir otni ssalc elddim reppu tuo gnigde dna
.thguoht I ,suoicipsus ytterP
.em ta gnirats s’eh
.cigam lautca od ot
.gniht siht tuoba noitamrofni yna drocer ot desu eb dluoc taht gnihtoN
.ecaf ruoy no mrow a s’taht fi ksa thgim enoemos eciov fo enot fo tros emas eht ni ,sksa ehs
,raeppasid meht ekam ot hguone yllaer t’nsi noitamrofni siht esac ni tsuj dnA
.peels ot gniyrt er’uoy nehw gniyonna si hcihw ,krad eht ni wolg yeht ,thgin tA .9
?meht erusaem uoy nehw raeppasid snrocinu dias I nehw rebmemeR
,yas I ”,yltcaxe ,suoregnad toN“   .gniog speek ehS
.ygoloiB laciteroehT—ahdduB ot raews—
,thgiled hsikruT ,napizram ,seirruc
elba eb ot sraeppa taht erutaerc lacitsatnaf a rof gnirac ereh tuo dnuora gnitraf naht emit ruo dneps ot srehcraeser su lla rof syaw retteb yaw era ereht skniht ehs llet nac uoy ,htaerb a ni sdrow owt naht erom syas reven ehs hguoht nevE
”.snigriv yb dehcuot eb ylno nac yehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”?uoy tuoba yas taht seod tahw oS“
.dnuorg eht revo lla oog raelc fo maerts suocsiv ,gnol siht stihs ti nehT
.laer t’nera snrocinu taht :yas ot tuoba er’uoy tahw wonk I os ,yakO
?dah uoy wenk reven uoy rewoprepus a ekil sleef ti dna
.denoitcnuf evah thgim serutaerc lacihtym woh tuoba lla s’tI
,erolklof dna sdnegel otni peed gnitteg trats eW
ygolirt sreraeB eriF ehT fo rohtua
saw sihT.niaga reve
od dluow elbisnes enoyna sa ,drawkcab selbmarcs eH
.oknob tib a mih edam s’noitalosI .flesym llet I ,llew hO
.dnalsi eht raen dewolla si nerdlihc htiw eno oN
,tnemom taht ni dnA
.yawa thgir tuo mih pleh t’nod I fi reddam neve steg eh
?thgir ,raf os taerg ytterp sdnuoS
.snrocinu tuoba lliw reve enoyna sa hcum sa wonk I ,em eveileB
,yawa raf yllaer s’ehs ekil ,eciov teiuq siht ni syas ehs ”,eeL“
.liat sih skcilf dna ,riah laicaf ecreif eht nwod gnivarb ylsuoicoref rof flesmih htiw desaelp s’eh ekil tort elttil a gnivig ,dnuora snrut eH
.riaf yltcaxe mees t’ndid hcihw
.dum ni degrembus-flah dna gniwolg dna derettacs lla meht fo lluf eloh pmud gib a s’ereht erehw
”dniM ruoY wolB yletelpmoC lliW tahT
ym ffo gnissip tnecrep evif-ytnewt
fo dnik siht teg I ,ti hcuot I sa noos sa dna
?suoregnad ti si ,yhW“
.rehto ro diolbat emos rof gnitirw knab ekam d’I noitaudarg retfa derugif I
.eriw evil a dehcuot ehs ekil gnihctiwt dna ffits lla og reh ees I dna ,drawrof eson sih segdun eH
.pmal gnidaer a htiw ksed erab a dna ,renroc eno ta toc elbatrofmocnu ,elttil a s’erehT
.gnihton hgiew yeht ekil ,doof htiw dellif setarc gnidaolnu trats ll’ehS
.htrof dna kcab gnippihw era seert eht ,sdnalsi retsis eht nO
.gnihtemos ro repeeK repparT a hguorht dekan
”?evil uoy erehw taht sI“
.tluaf ym si siht lla ekil
.su ta gnihgual s’eh erus ytterp m’I
erac ekat ot tnaw uoy fi sksa enoemos nehw on yas t’nac uoy
”?won ereh fo tuo gnitteg eb I dluohS“
.ereh nees eb t’nac eW
.seinnub ekil dekcuf neht dna ranimes gnilaeh lacisyhpatem emos gnirud egelloc ym ta pu dekooh I dna ehS
.nwod dna pu gnicnuob ,em ot slley ehs ”!eeL“
,skrow ti woh dna deneppah tahw tuoba snoitseuq eseht lla gniksa s’ehs
,nigriv a em edam sretsnom esohT
meht draug ot tog ev’I
yawa tort gnicnarp siht sevig eH
elihw puc puos a rof retaw emos pu taeh I oS
.ecaf ym ni hsulb eht leef nac I
erif ehtaerb dna ylf ot elba neeb evah thgim snogard woh no esitaert tnaig a daer ev’uoy otni efil ruoy detsaw ev’uoy ekil tlef reven ev’uoy ,em eveileB
.snrocinu lautca htiw krow ot aisenodnI ot pirt a ekam ot ekil d’I woh sksa
?eerged laer a si siht ,suoires si siht ,dad on taht nwod dna pu erows I retfa
.srehcraeser rof erom s’ti yllaer tub
snrocinU tuobA stcaF elbaveilebnU 6“
tpecxe noitcerid yna ,llew ,dna edis ot edis morf kcen lufrewop sih sehcnerw eh sa gnikahs sllaw esuoh eht yb deinapmocca si siht yllausU
,wonk I sa raf sa ,ereh xis rebmun tcaf ot teg uoy emit eht yb dnA .gniyl t’nsaw I
.eerf mih llup ot kcen sih dnuora smra ym tup dna edistuo nur I
ro ylluferac dna ylwols yllaer gniht fo dnik siht nrael ot evah ew nialpxe I
,od uoy sa noos sA .derusaem ro detroper gnieb ediba t’nac snrocinU
,akuY dneirflrig ym htiw teb neknurd tnecrep net ,dad
”?ti htiw dnah a em evig uoy naC .t’nseod tI“
.od I os ,eerf mih llup og dna
.enihsnus dna seiks eulb s’ti s’ereh tuB
lufpleh eb dluow knil tiddeR a dna ,deefzzuB ,dekcarC ebyam—ot epoh I setisbew eht lla no pu siht teg I fi dnA
,ydaerla em gnitib era sgub
,eerf saisetC teg I
.llaw eht ot kcuts daeh sih htiw ffuts tnatropmi gniod neeb dah eh ekil noisserpxe deyonna ,ythguah siht em sevig tsuj eH
,stuohs ehs ”!eromyna ot tnaw reven uoY“
.sdaeherof rieht fo tuo pu gnikcits
.eromyna ereht ton er’yeht
.nerdlihc on sah ehs tub
”?pots lliw ti ,dnalsi eht evael uoy fi
.ytirutam lauxes fo psuc eht ot ygoloib ruoy steser cigam nehw ti llac uoy revetahw ro ,niaga htuoy fo hsulb lluf eht ni gnieb ylneddus ot desu teg ot gniyrt ,deb eht no nwod stis ehS
.tihs nrocinu fo elddup raelc ,gib a ni gnippets morf reh pots ot etal oot ,yas I
.htaed ot sevlesmeht gnivrats nageb yeht ,yna meht evag eno on nehw dna
.akuY ,dneirflrig ym tuoba klat ot evah I erehw si sihT
,detsixe dna laer era snrocinu dias I nehw tuB
,sesu taob s’irtuP taht ycneuqerf emas eht no gnitsacdaorb eb ot deneppah
,saisetC gnideef tuoba em sllet eH
.naeco eht revo tuo gnirats yad ym fo tol a dneps I oS
,pu sevig eh yllanif litnu ,elbmuts gniknalc ,gnilgnag a era spets wef tsal ehT
.dnalsi eht raen dewolla si nerdlihc htiw eno on yhw
.gnol woh swonk doG rof dnalsi siht no ereh tuo kcuts yug rooP
.ot desoppus ton er’ew ,neht tub ,nwod gnihtyna etirw reh nees reven ev’I .sdon ehS
,laer erew yeht yfirev ot gnol os koot ti yhw s’taht smees tub ,ecnetsixe fo tuo kniw ro ,enalp rehtona ot og
.thgif ot dediced evah taht srallipretac owt ekil rehtegot emoc sworbeye reH
.yllautca ,eurt t’nsi sihT
,knip yllacipyt era seye riehT .8
”.retteb yna steg reven ti
.yako yllatot si gnihtyreve
.eip emil yek ekil sllems eH
”.lla s’taht ,won thgir ot tnaw t’nod
,yduts ot woh tuo derugif s’eno on taht nonemonehp gnizama dna erar siht era snrocinu esuaceb taht snialpxe izuaF oS
ffo sedils enizagam ehT
”!uoy tuoba ton s’tI
,deroloc-wobniar ro ,teloiv
,nosaes noosnom ton s’ti nehw erom
.rehtie uoy tuoba ton s’tI“
elip ysaerg gib a no spils eh tub ,esroh ysatnaf yrgna fo not dilos a yb degrahc gnieb nehw
.oot ,taht ot teg ll'I
.draeb kcalb gib ,daeh gnidlab ,llat
,gniog ,tuo dnah reh htiw saisetC no pu gnipeerc ,esuoh ym raen reh dnif I
doof rehto yna desufer dna ,gniwohs erew sbir rieht litnu gnitae
.flesym llet neve t’nac I tahw
.sraey eerht tsal eht neeb ev’I erehw s’taht oS
em ot sneppah siht dnA   .taht ekiL
,otatop ypmul a ekil skool ecaf reH
,tseretni eniuneg tnecrep neetfif
sdnah ym hsaw ,knis eht ni sehsid tup dna
swercskroc lahwran htiw sesroh etihw tes-yot tnaig ,wonk uoY
.os kniht t’nod I“ .daeh ym ekahs I
,trams ,yxes s’ehS
sdraeb ,syas izuaF ,esuaceb nevahs naelc peek ot desoppus m’I
dellac ssalc a ekat ot dah I
.kcod eht no edanomel yrrebwarts deredwop fo xob gib a spmud irtuP ,tnurg a htiW
,eciov tsecin ym ni mih llet I
dewohs srehcraeser tsrif eht nehW .tae ot desoppus era snrocinu skniht eh tahw s’ti esuaceb s’taht ,llet nac ew sa raf sA
.edaced a ni nees s’eh nosrep tsrif eht m’I ekil
srehtiw eht ta sdnah 02-61 tuoba dnats snrocinU .7
.t’nod I taht nwod dna pu raews I nehw netsil t’nseod dna ,meht tnaw ll’I syaS
”!xes ta dab os erew uoy yhw s’tahT“
”.ti hcuot t’nod tsuj ,kool ,dnim reveN“
,em ot noitcaer elbanosaer a smees hcihw ,saisetC gniredrum-etah diova ot esuoh eht edisni em swollof akuY oS
”?wonk uoy ,dneirflrig a tog ev’I tub gnihtyreve dna looc s’tI“
deppots tsuj yeht ekiL
tenalpruF hguorht ro
staob rof kcehc ll’I
,boj niam ym s’tahT
,ti ecaf s’tel tub—
”!tihs fo eceip uoy ,niaga nigriv a eb t’nac I .kcuf eht tahW“
.edam reve ydnac fo dnik yreve ylraen dna ,sessalom erup
.taht ekil gnihtemos ro mosnar rof dleh eb ot gniog m’I
.boj laer a tnaw t’ndid uoY .gnihtyna ta krow ot tnaw reven uoY
.tuo dnif reven I .ffo ti stuhs taht eno eht
.sevael dna ssarg yltsom eta snrocinu eht ,pu
.htaed ot deracs m’I esuaceb ,ti tuoba kniht neve t’nac I
.yltnegru erom dna reduol gniknow si saisetC   ”.nwod
. . . ti ,ereht gnittis tsuj wobniar a
eye teloiv ylgnitatirri eno htiw em ta gniralg si saisetC dna pu ylerab s’nus eht ,edistuo og I nehW
dnuora gnihsarht s’eh dna ,esuoh eht ni kcuts s’nroh sih esuaceb yzarc ekil gniknow si saisetC ,gninrom eno nehT
.nrop yag naisenodnI fo dnik emos ylnialp ytterp
.rof era sffumrae eht tahw s’taht—
.niaga reganeet a saw I ekil tlef I
.era uoy tahw si ,elohssa na er’uoY“
.mih erongi I tub ,edistuo mrala ni gniknow si saisetC   ”.era
.dettep eb ot eson etihw gib sih gnirewol s’eh dna
.ypeerc teg ot strats tI
,ti ta ssa ym tsub I ,revetahw oS
.tnatsid erom erew uoy ,tisiv ot kcab emac uoy emit yrevE .teiuq os tnew uoY .em llet t’ndluoc uoy wenk I“ .snworf ehS   .ezeehw I ”?em
.seilppus eht htiw htnom a ecno tuoba meht gnignirb strats irtuP ,retal htnom a dnuora nehT
.thgil fo shtgnelevaw detimil ot detcejbus nehw neve murtceps roloc lluf a stcarfer ruf rieht dna
,noitcif s’ti kniht lla uoy fi neve—
fo secart eht dnuos eht ni raeh I dna ,srekcin tI
,srehtorb owt reh dna dneirflrig yM
.seilppus s’irtuP teg ot skcod eht ot nwod daeh I .nosaes noosnoM
.yaw reh ni gnitteg ylno saw I noisserpmi eht em evag ehs tub ,pleh ot yrt ot desu I
.nrocinu a tep ot tnaw reven yllaer uoY .5
.reh llet I ”,selttikS“
,ebyam ,haey syas eh dna ,ksa I ?srehcaoP
,yduts ot detnaw yllautca I tahw saw ti nwod dna pu erows I retfa siht no tiuq I fi taht
gnihton yllacisab htiw dnalsi eht otno pu em sdnes maet hcraeser eht ,oga sraey eerht dnalsi eht no devirra tsrif I nehW
”!neht lla ta yag t’nsaw I !eurt ton s’tahT“
.tius drazah eht htiw rehtob t’nod I os
,esolc gnimoc trats yeht fi dna
.ot tnaw t’nod yllaer I dna ,dnuora loof yllausu ew ,drawretfa ylnO
.dniw a t’nsi ereht dna ,dniw eht ni gniwollib enaM .cigam dna thgil fo nocaeb gniloord ,gnitraf eht ,saisetC s’ereht dna kcab kool I
.not eno yletamixorppa hgiew dna
yojne esaelP   .flowafoS dna
wedlim ekil tib elttil a sllems ehS
.fooh eno no kcuts tekcub doof sih steg dna
htiw nigeb ot detseretni taht reven saw I taht pu ssef ,od ot gniog I ma tahw tub ,ssa eht ni niap a s’ti dna ,krow laer od ot evah I neddus a fo lla ,yawynA
.gniht eht yb dexifsnart ylnialp s’ehs esuaceb ,reh retfa pu ekih I dna
.selkcirp niks yM ”?tahW“
”.laer s’ti eveileb t’nac I .laer s’tI“
.irtuP ta erats I
,mraw dna tfos-tibbar si ruf siH
.won ,ekil er’yeht tahw wonk lla uoy esuaceB
,eeL ,dog ym ho ,gnizama os s’tahT“
.si ehs dlo woh llet ot drah s’tI
”. . . em ees ot emac uoy semit wef tsal eht snaem taht os ,tiaW“   ”.skcus tI
.ydnac no sucof yletinifed yeht tub
.flesym gnitcidartnoc m’I ekil skool ti won wonk I
”.ylbaborP .haey ,hU“ .hguoc I
,taob elttil nwo reh ni gnitiaw eb lliw irtuP erehw kcod eht no tuo og ll’I
.ti skcatta dna lamina tnaig a rof ti sekatsim gninrom eht ni dna ,stsixe esuoh eht stegrof eh ,peels ot seog eh nehw thgin yreve kniht I
.wef a tiaw ot reh ksa tub ,haey yas I
,ynapmoc reh tnaw tsuj yltsom I dna
.sdik dah reven eh taht naem tsum taht
.dnalsi eht morf ffo elpoep eracs ot meht esu ot tog ev’I esuaceB .snug ,haeY
.yag er’uoy snaem taht ,repeek nrocinu a er’uoy fI .4
.ti rof gniog ton m’I dna
,gnideef tuoba snialpxe eh os ,boj eht tuoba mih ksa dna ffo ti gurhs I
.modgniK denworD eht fo aoK dna
.loohcs ssenisub ni delliK
dnalsi eht otni rehtruf daeh I nehT
.ta tohs gnieb ekil t’nod yeht dna ,srehcraeser neeb s’taob yreve raf os tub ,resolc emoc evah thgim yeht ,srehcaop erew yeht fI
.yrtnuoc eht ni ygoloozotpyrc ni seerged lautca ylno eht fo eno tog ev’uoy nehw yllaicepse
,tenretnI on dna saremac on era ereht dnalsi eht no tuB
s’erehT .nwod deid lla ti ,oediv yna teg dluoc eno on
”,zeeT ,uoy kcuF“
.secneuqesnoc sah
”?wollip ruoy rednU“
:yawa thgir mih ezingocer I tub
.srozar ytefas fo ylppus yhtlaeh a htiw moorhtab ynit A
tsuj taob s’rehtaf reh ebyaM .taht ekil gnihtemos ro detiucric-trohs ro deggulpnu tog ti ebyaM
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
yletelpmoC lliW tahT
.nigriv a won s’dad reh ,eeS
.eurt si draeh ylbaborp ev’uoy ffuts eht fo tol A
srewop ylhtraenu rieht yb deifirroh os saw eh ,aisenodnI ni snrocinu dessentiw tsrif oloP ocraM nehW .01
,niaga saisetC ot tuo gnihcaer s’ehs ,edistuo teg I nehW
.reh llet I ”,ydaerla eerht esoht fo owt er’uoy ,llew ,haeY“
.ereht tuo staob on era ereht erus ekam ot em evag yeht epocselet a htiw retaw eht nacs dna kcod eht ot nwod og ll’I ,nwod delttes s’eh ecnO   .sloord dna
.snug eht tuoba dnA
”.emit yreve nigriv a saw I“
yas tsuj s’tel os ,liated otni teg ot tnaw t’nod yllaer I
.dnalsi eht raen repap ro nep oN
ssik a em gnivig dna em tsniaga flesreh gnihsams ,em ot pu snur dna reip eht otno pu selbmarcs ehS
?erew yas I od yhW
.airebiS ro anihC ebyaM ”.devresbo“
,)ekarDnePehT@( llebpmaC nayR yb
”,yrrow t’noD“   ”.yap ehS“
deb fo tuo llor I litnu gniknow peek ll’eH
,yad ot yad morf egnahc secnereferp siH
.og ot dah I neht dna ,deneppah gniht nrocinu elohw eht nehw ecalp a teg ot desoppus erew eW
.nrubdniw morf der dna nus eht morf nworb
,ecalp tsrif eht ni ereh m’I yhw fo tnemugra dlo eht pu sgnirb esruoc fo hcihW
.drawkwa tsuj ;yvaeh ton s’tI
”.gnihtemos ro gninosiop noitaidar ekiL
dna edisa em sekat iksneiwrezC .rD ,rosseforp yrotsiH larutannU ym ,raey roines ym dna
.ydob elohw ym revo lla egrahc ygrene
a taht sI“ .sepag ehS
:snosaer laer eht reh llet nac I ,emit tsrif eht rof ,emit siht ylnO
.hguone s’taht dnA
.woh wonk t’nod I“
s’ti tuB“   ”.t’nod yllaer I“
.ecnetsixe fo tuo dneirflrig ym depiw dna ,yag em denrut
”.haey ,wobniar A“   ”—a—
etah I taht yalpsid dirul ylralucitrap a ot nepo syalps dna
.em fo tsrow etulosba eht gnigduj
.ta gnikool pots t’nac I taht
dnif uoy did woH“
,syas akuY ”,dog ym hO“
.foorp-ecneics era snrocinU
.diputs erew snrocinu esuaceB .nac lla eW
.shtnom thgie tuoba daeha pikS .gnorW
.emit elgnis yreve
,oot ffo og lliw taht mrala detacitsihpos a tog ev’eW
.tuo mih llup dna kcen gib sih otno barg I neht dna
.tib elttil a reh etah I ,tnemom taht nI
”—a ton m’I dna ,ti dehcuot I tuB“
.reip eht ot nwod daeh dna
.aisenodnI ni sdnalsi lareves no dethgis neeb evah snrocinu taht srosseforp ruo morf raeh lla ew raey eromohpos ym retfa nehT
.raew ot desoppus er’ew tius drazah eht tuoba uoy dlot I
.6   .detsixe reven
,sediseb dna ,oga emit gnol a delias pihs taht
:uoy rof stcaf erom wef a era ereh
dna kcirt lufwa fo tros emos lla si siht taht dnim ym ni tbuod on
”?yddaD“ .pu skool ehS
.eb ot desu akuY erehw
.dniheb riah a neve gnivael tuohtiw gniraeppasid fo tibah dab a evah yeht dna denialpxe eb t’nac taht tihs fo tol a od yehT
.tnemnorivne eht otni tuo teg yeht fi od lliw sgniht eseht tahw erus s’eno oN
,snoitacav no nevE
:strats yllamron yad ym woh s’ereH
.gnisucca dna yrgna era
.nrocinu a tep ot tnaw reven uoY .3   .ecid on os
.ereh eb t’ndluohs ehs yhw snosaer ynam os era erehT .sselhceeps
ni gnihsur ria eht lla morf palcrednuht erutainim a saw ,tuo derugif retal I ,dnuos tahT
?cigam tsniaga ,tahW“
.slaeh sehcuot nroh sih gnihtyrevE
.efil ym fo tser eht rof worc gnitae eb d’I
.odibil tsuj lla s’ti tsrif tA
.emils dna dum ni gniwollaw ecnereferp yb emit rieht dneps yehT
,suoegrog :ti ees I dna
.yletal fo tsom gnitae neeb sah saisetC tahw era swollamhsram dna selttikS ehT
,yggum dna toh si ria eht ,deracs m’I
.wobniar eht fo dne eno pu kcip I
.tsixe t’nod snrocinU
,tnedicca yb saisetC dehcuot I emit tsrif eht did I ekil psag mih ees I
!srotcod era erehT“
,emit eht lla nwot ni t’nsaw ehS
”.won ma I ohw s’ti ,akuY ,desufnoc tsuj m’I ekil ton s’tI
.slamina tnegilletni ton era snrocinU .1   .ti fo llA
.dnalsi elohtihs elttil ypmaws a no nrocinu a revo hctaw gnipeeK
,llebpmaC nayR yb
”?ereh no gniog s’tahw ,yenoH“
.em teem ot nwod semoc ,em erofeb repeek eht saw ohw yug eht ,izuaF ,yawynA
.esuoh eht fo tuo nur I
.gniht eht s’ereH
,si eh taht erutaerc diputs ylbidercni ,saisetC
.toc eht no ylivaeh nwod stis ehS
.etalocohc dna sregrubmah tpecxe
.peels ym ni ym no despalloc evah yllautneve dluow ecalp ym ,flesti xif t’ndid ti fi dna gninrom gnikaerf yreve ylraen esuoh ym fo tuo ti llup ot evah I esuaceb ,doog si hcihW
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
deb eht rednu ffuts hsup ,ni nur I
.eerf teg ot woh wonk ot mid oot dna
.xes si tuoba kniht nac I lla ,ylnedduS
.eerged ysae na htiw egelloc etaudarg d’I derugif I esuaceb flah doog a dna
siht seod eH .drawkcab
.seert eht otni ti swollof ehs dna ,dnalsi eht pu sdaeh dna seinnihw tI
.erutaerc eht erusaem dna
.sees ehs tahw sseug ot evah t’nod I
.elttil a pu ydit dluohs I erugif I neht tub—
,elttil a gnireggats ,snrut ehS
.tenalp eht fo ecaf eht ffo srekcuf esoht depiw evah ll’I
,ekiL .raeppasid yeht
.ot klat ot enoemos
.tihs nrocinu eht lla yawa gnihsaw rof pmup retaw eht dna ,tius drazah eht tuoba em sllet
,ti od yeht yhw wonk neve t’nod eW
.redluohs ym revo pu gnirats ,ffo sliart akuY ”. . .naem I
.tenretnI eht no tihs taht kcits dna aremac a htiw edistuo nur ot naht erom gnihton detnaw dna ,gniknow
.ereh em rof tliub yeht esuoh elttil eht fo edis eht otni nroh sih gnimmals ,nrocinu ym ,saisetC s’tI
.rehtea eht otni hsinav
.sarbacapuhc ro itey ekil serutaerc elat klof fo yduts eht ,wonk uoy—
.dad s’dneirflrig ym fo eson eht ssorca kcilf liat taht fo sdnarts wef A
.pu kaerb tsuj dluohs ew ebyam taht tnatsid os nettog ev’I syas dna
”!uoy pleh nac ohw stsigolohcysP
,hcamots reh woleb nwod sdnah reh stup dna
.dad s’akuY drawot thgir egrahc gnilialf-teppuM a seod saisetC .haeY ?sdraeb dna snrocinu tuoba dias I tahw erofeb rebmemeR
”.dlrow elohw eht ni enoyna fo boj tselooc eht evah uoy
”.lufituaeb os s’tI
,trihs reh rednu dnah ym gnittup ,em tsniaga pu lla s’ehS
neddus a fo lla oS
.dnalsI nrocinU no skeew wef tsrif esoht dab ytterp reh gnissim m’I ,llitS
.erehwemos em rof boj a dnif ll’ehs dna emoh kcab emoc dna tiuq tsuj t’nac I yhw
,nwod ti knay annog s’eh deracs m’I ,drah os
”.ta kool ot seturb ylgu yrev era yehT
tahw tuoba klat reve t’ndluow uoY
.ereht dna ereh owt ro keew a rof levart gnirud ni gnippots fo tniop a ekam dluow ehs dna ,yako krow gniht ecnatsid eht edam ew tub
llebpmaC nayR yb ”dniM ruoY wolB
.ylwols sneppah ti kniht I .os kniht t’nod I ,oN“
,esle ecalpemos tropelet tsuj yeht fi erus rof swonk eno oN
.esrow lla s’ti tuB
”.ereh em del irtuP yllautneve neht dna
.saisetC no sdnuor ehS
”. . . gniht taht naem uoy ,dog ym hO“
,ecnenamrep tcejbo fo stpecnoc cisab tsom eht neve gnikcal eno
nozamA no gnitirw sih dnif nac uoY
,stekcit enalp dnuof ,stpiecer drac tiderc dekcart eW
.tuoba eb ot desoppus saw ygoloozotpyrc tahw reven si em ksa uoy fi hcihw ,ton thgim tahw dna laer eb thgim tahw tuo gnirugiF
yrots s’yadot dna
,redluohs ym revo kool I emit yreve tuB
”,niaga nigriv a er’uoY“
.scinahcem mutnauq fo gnidnatsrednu mid ytterp a dna srewop lacigam ylnialp fo tol a gnivah morf semoc ti taht stnemugra dilos emos era ereht tub
”dniM ruoY wolB yletelpmoC lliW tahT snrocinU tuobA stcaF elbaveilebnU 6“   si
tsuj m’I   ”!esirpruS“
.yhw nialpxe nac eno on dna
.tseisae s’revetahw tuoba tsuj s’tI
moderob eht ffo evats ot yaw ysae oN .enohp oN
,esoprup no raeppasid ti ekam tsuj dluohs ew syas dna elims yppahnu ,lufwa siht steg ehS
kool a evah ot dnuor emoc thgim ohw elpoeP .srehpargotohP .stsitneicS
tsuj I .gnihtyreve fo tuo laed gib a hcus gnikam tiuQ“ ,yas I dnA
.reh eveileb yllatot I taht toN“   .sgurhs irtuP
.skoobeton on ,potpal on ,enohp on—
.thgie-ytnewt ylno s’ehs dna snoitacol rotcarporihc eerht snwO
,sffumrae ym barg ll’I ,gnikcatta era snogard ekil rorret ni dnuora gnipollag dna gniknow s’eh elihW
.skced woleb morf pu spets akuY neht dna ,kcod eht no soerO fo xob gib a spmud irtuP
.snrocinu tuoba deiduts dna denrael ev’I gnihtyreve
.drawkcab dnuora denrut s’daeh ruoy ro ,ecaf ruoy gnikcatta tac a s’ti kniht yeht ekiL
.gnikool m’I erehw sees ehs dna ,yas I ”,parC“
reh llet ot woh kniht ot gniyrt ,roolf eht no nwod tis I ”.naem I“   ”?nehT“
,noitamrofni hcum ton
,nrocinu evil laer a fo
.rotaregirfer ym fo ediskcab eht eb thgim ekil skool tahw ni yadot deirub
gnidaer trats uoy emit eht morf degnahc evah lliw taht llA
.tihs yzal a tsuj
.ffo tnew reven mrala xorp eht yhw wonk t’nod I ,yad siht oT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
sdnah reh hsaw ot ni reh etivni ot tuoba m’I
.sgnithgis demrifnoc fo stol retfa neve
.niar esnetni fo wodahs eht ees nac I ,dnalsi eht morf syaw elttil A
”!nuR !yletaidemmi ereh morf yawa teg ot evah uoY“ .tuohs I ”!kcab teG“
.nosaer doog a fo kniht ot yrt I ”. . . s’tI“
.wodniw eht tuo skool ehS   ”?ereh s’dad ruoY“
.su rof lausu si hcihw ,thgif elttil a evah ew dna gnillortnoc reh llac I dna
,elfir dna ,epocselet
?wonk uoy ,reve erofeb ti deknay reven ev’I ekil s’tI
.pu em sekaw tahw si dnuos tsrif tahT !knoooooW !knoooooW !mahW
.boj a fo tuo eb d’I neht
.hsinif uoy emit eht ot
.gnihtyna wonk t’nod I esruoc fo dna
.sraeppasid nrocinu eht
.mih ta daeh ym ekahs I
serutaerc elbirroh eseht tuo gnikees morf enoyna reted ot os gniod yb depoh eH
sedulcni meht deef ot dah ev’I tahw fo tsil ehT
.snrocinu lacissalc ekil kool yeht yltnerappa taht tpecxe
esruoc fo tuB .snahregnaL fo stelsI ym gnissim htab eci na ni pu ekaw ot gniog m’I dna macs lufwa fo tros emos lla si siht lacitpeks m’I esruoc fo dnA
.saisetC fo tuo tihs laretil eht gniracs ,ffo og lliw mrala xorp eht
”.swollamhsram dnA“
.evitceted a htiw nwod uoy detnuh I oS
si tahw fo kcats a osla s’ereht ,toc eht rednu devohs-flaH .tuo dna ni yad
.saisetC hcuot uoy nehw sneppah ti kniht I
nehw dna skeew owt tuoba rof sevawria eht lla tiH
.reh rebmemer llits nac I tpecxE
.skced s’irtuP woleb taerg ton s’ti gnisseug m’I—
,em ta kcab serats
”.ereht ti tfel em erofeb yug ehT“
.ti hcuot I emit yreve em ot sneppaH“ .yas I
seye reH ”.yag erew uoy em llet t’ndluoc uoY
.ti tuoba seirots swen feirb eht rebmemer thgim uoY
.gnihtemos ro god dimit a s’ti ekil ”!yob ,ereh emoC“
tuoba ot tuo emoc snosaer eht dna ,ti otni tnew I yhw em ksa elpoeP
.snrocinu tuo kaerf
a tsuj er’uoy won dnA .pihsnoitaler ruo no krow ot detnaw reven uoY .dleif laer a yduts ot tnaw t’ndid uoY
.denrecnoc gnidnuos ,edistuo morf syas eciov s’nam a ”?yenoH“
.ma I naht regnuoy ylbaborp s’eh ecnis esac eht eb t’nac taht hguohtlA
,esuoh eht fo edis eht ni kcuts ti ot pu nekow ev’I nehw sgninrom neeb evah erehT
.mih dnuora eb tsuj ebyam rO
:gnidaer er’uoy tahw kool ,llew ,haeY
taht tuo tniop I dna
.gnorts ylhsikaerf tub ,ynit s’ehS
.nonnac nmad a derif tsuj ev’I ekil retaw eht revo tuo gnikcarc seog dnuos ehT
.eromyna rebmemer etiuq t’nac I seno eht
.derob s’ehs ekil sksa ehS ”?yadot tahW“
.gniht fo tros taht ,sgnithgis htiw stnemucod dlo gnitalsnart
.retupmoc on s’ereht tuB
”!dnalsI nrocinU no nigriv yag a—
,ekil ,esahp a tsuj s’ti ebyaM“
.ydnac nottoc mraw ekil elttil a sleef tI
.tuo devom eh retfa hsart eht ni senizagam s’izuaF lla depmud I
.pu delaeh sah llaw eht ni eloh eht ,oslA