krow fo yad tsrif sih nigeb ot tuoba saw eh sa tsuj dedne ew dna
.ereht sfloW-ytiC wollef yna ees t'ndluoc I
,wor tnorf eht ni sexof fo ylimaf a s'erehT
"?dniheb enoyreve gnivael tuoba deirrow ton er'uoY"  .ti wenk I
.seilleb rieht desopxe dna skcab rieht otno dellor yletaidemmi kcaP eht fo srebmem eht fo llA
".evol htob nac ew ecalp a dnif stel"
,dne eht ta rufnooM ot detniop flow nworb eht "...dna ,uoy ,uoy ,uoy
",taht ekil gnihtemoS"
,shtuom ruo derolpxe dna tem seugnot ruo sA
,flow dekcinap a retfa esahc ot tnaw t'ndid tub
,yaw taht yats dluow ti depoh I dnA
.og ot dedeen ew erehw ot mih gniwollof
fo trap lanif dna
?!yrotcaf gniredner krop A"
,dniheb morf em degguh dna
.saw laed gib eht tahw dnatsrednu t'nod llits I"
.staes ytpme eb dluow ereht taht dedulcnoc dna htam eht enod dah noorA
.rehtaew eht dna ,sllems ecin
,esruoc fO  .evac-tfig eht ni
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
",owt uoy sa doog sa kool sretfird attol a toN"
.ecaf ym fo tnorf ni hteet sih deppans rufnooM
lauxes ton s'taht tub sessa s'rehto hcae tsniaga skcoc ruo pmuh thgim eW
.mih htiw ni bmilc em pleh ot nwod dehcaer neht dna
.daeh ym fo tuo sthguoht hcus koohs I tub
,krop gnissecorp no krow ot teg ,uoy fo tser ehT
.reeuq erew uoy taht kcaP elohw eht dlot rufnooM sulp...yawa
?ot tnaw I did dnA
,ahplA eht rof ekops flow nworb eht
".siht od ot tnaw llits I"
ni denael noorA
.su fo htob rof ecap fo egnahc a eb dluow nwot llams A
.daor worran a nwod dna
ecnartne llams a otni em del rufnooM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.evresbo uoy ,tnacilppA
,srennid s'thgin tsal
",uoy wonk ot gnilliw m'I tub oot uoy wonk ylerab I"
,ysiad a sa kaew sa dna
hsulf ecaf ym tlef I
nekorb ylurt saw ecnatsiser yM
...os kcaP eht did os
",og steL"  .ti kcuF
".taht s'taht dna ,wohs a fo tib a meht evig ,tib a woc eht no wang ,hteet ruo kroc ew os
"?elbatpecca si riahcleehw s'ahplA eht woh ekiL"
.ni gnilkcirt nageb stsiruot eht sa denihw noorA  .xes citsilamina ,waR .xes ekil
!oga seirutnec siht ekil evil t'ndid sevloW
,nevig noitcerid rehto on htiW
,kcaP eht nioj dna dniheb ytic eht evael ot tnemtimmoc a edam dah I
.ti eerf ylluf dluoc I taht os kcaP eht ta kcab erew ew dehsiw yltrap I
".kcab og syawla nac I
anera eht otni dna moorkaolc eht morf degreme sevlow eht sa
,detrons rufnooM
;ahplA eurt a ekil yaw eht del noorA    .derepsihw I
.stnemtaert repmetsid gninnab elihw
.anera eht deretne ti litnu raer eht no ti gnippals ylthgil noorA htiw ni gnilpmart emac woc gnuoy A
a dna roolf gnillik krop a tuohtiw tekram nabru eht ni evititepmoc niamer ot yaw on tsuj s'ereht...haeY"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.seye dehctamsim sih otni derats I dna
.seilppus fo lluf moor-kaolc a dah hcihw sdnats eht etisoppo
",rufnooM ,eyA"  ".foop ruf rieht ekam dna thgirf a meht evig
dellems ti ,ti kcuF  ...etisiuqxe taht fo amora eht naht renif
,gnorw og ot gniog saw gnihtemos wenk tsuj I dna
.no gniog saw tahw ot sa desufnoc etiuq em gnivael ,em desserdda meht fo enoN
.seert fo gnipporc a hguorht gnidael
"!yrewerB hcnaR dlO"
sih ni saw wap yM
"?retcarahc dliub spleh ti yltnerappA
no gniog saw tahw tuoba mih ksa ot detpmet saw I
,eson sih htiw dnuora deffins eH
,no kcab delbmuts revird ehT
"...eno rehtona ton...on hO"
,kcab eht ni mih otno despalloc I
elohpeep eht ot revo deklaw ylwols I "...hu
,yawhgih eht no nades gnissap a ta tuo bmuht ym gnidloh dehgis I
",hguone lwoh t'ndid ew emit tsaL"
...rof ereh emac I tahw ton si sihT"
sredluohs sih dehcaer tsomla yeht taht wol os gnipoord erew slwoj siH
.ronam s'ahplA eht ot txen sdoow eht hguorht tsuj s'ti ,haeY"  "?!suoires uoy erA
.mih reted ot mees t'ndid ti tub ,trihs-t ",kcaP eht htiW nooM eht ta delwoH I"
"?no gniog si lleh eht tahw..."
!ekatsim fo dnik emos eb tsum..."
,gnizama gnihtemos fo gninnigeb eht saw ti tub
.redluohs ym ta deffins noorA dna
.sresuort ym ni gniworg serised nwo ym erongi ot deirt osla I ,esiwekiL
,seirots noitcif ecneics yrruf yttums ylsselemahs gnitirw syojne ohw ,xofpoF yb
,htaehs ruoy ffo swap ruoy peek dna"
.eliforp yrrufoS sih no htlif yhcnuar sih fo erom daer nac uoY
delbmur kcurt eht sa gnihgual
,flow nworb gnikool-derit a yb dellor riahcleehw a ni gnittiS
semit laveidem ni tes eivom a morf tnemanruot gnitsuoj a enigamI
"?ellivneerG ni ereht s'tahW
,yap ym eciwt emoh gnikat ni deifitsuj leef dluoc eh taht os tsuj
".kcab boj ym rof geb dna pu kcas tsuj dluohs I ebyam..." ,deggurhs I "...os
"?rehtegot yawa nur annaW"
meht no snagols gnitekram htiw depmats shtolcniol gnilles dna ni sevlow gnirobhgien gnitivni sevlow-evac cirotsiherp denigami I
"!ereh tub erehwynA"
ylpeed delworg noorA dna denaom I
.skroc fo aes eht tsdima teef ym ot teg ot pleh s'noorA dedeen I ,niaga ecnO
,eciton ym ni dednah I
sa hcus sgniht nevlow dradnats-gob ylriaf tuoba tahc ot dedeecorp srebmem eht mohw fo
"?yllaer ,kcuF" ,denihw noorA  ".meht
skroc fo lluf xob nepo na otni llef ttub yM
.sresuort gniglub sih pu gnileef nageb dna hctorc s'noorA ot nwod dehcaer I dna
,wodniw kcab eht hguorht kcab dellac god eht
,hteet ytsan ylralucitrap htiw flow nworb a fo redluohs eht pota wap etihw a gnicalP
".gniniatsus-fles saw kcaP eht thguoht I"
.dekeirhs xof a "!HGUONE"
.tnacifingis gnihtyna pu revoc ot deliaf taht shtolcniol dna edih fo skaolc gniraew erew srehto elihw
...I"  ".su fo htob ot wen erehwemos ,esle erehwemos og stel nehT"  .derepsihw I
,rufnooM dniheb ecnatsid a ta tperc I
,yawhgih eht otno tog ew nehW
,teef rieht ot gniromalc yldeticxe nageb kcaP eht fo srebmem ehT
.doow fo edam muidats llams a sa ebircsed ylno dluoc I tahw saw hsub eht dnoyeb morf gnigremE
.seye sih fo ueil ni kcaP eht fo sllems eht ni gnikat
"!WON ,erauqs eht ot teG"
,tnatsni na nihtiW
"?gnihtemos ro krow rof gnikool uoy"
,delworg rufnooM
,did rufnooM naht sessik nevlow ot noitcudortni retteb a em evag eH
eson sih dekcil noorA  .deddon I
,noorA ta delims dna dnuora denrut I
",ngiapmac gnitekram yppans
!yrrehs fo seton gniyrrac ,ela deripsni na ylurt saw elA elpirT naigleB riehT" .demaeb I
,em tuo gnilrans ,drawrof degnul flow nworb eht
.tsaf oot gnivom erew sgniht ekil tlef I tnemom a rof
erom kool meht ekam ot dengised
,deb kcurt eht sdrawot denoitom god eht
",nrob saw I erofeb gnol ,oga sedaced ti no detov kcaP eht
,sub ruot ytpme eht otno deppils eW
?lortnoc rednu emoh morf yawa nur ot dediced ohw flow a peek yllaer I dluoc tuB
.rae ym ssorca derepsihw htaerb toh sih sa
eromyna floW-ytiC a t'nsaw I
a fo erom ,tuoba gniklat er'uoy tahw aedi on tog I" ,dehgual god ehT
.pu denepo dna nwod draug ym tel I litnu spil ym gnola eugnot sih gninnur dna
".ecalp siht tfel reven ev'I dna taht wonk I nevE" .deggurhs noorA
”kcaP eht snioJ floW ytiC A“   :yojne esaelP
,dnuorg eht otno llef I sa ffo flesym tuc I "...si sihT"
.erauqs gnitnuh eht ot revo teG .uoy"
"?yako ,gnilwoh evol stsiruoT
delttes traeh yM
",em ksa uoy fi elbatpecca etiuq s'taht tuB !yltcaxE"
",kcab og ot detnaw I dias reven I"
kcen ym fo kcab eht dnuora swaj sih deppans flow a dna em dniheb lworg yvaeh a saw erehT
enummoc eht morf yawa gnilbmur erofeb
"?detcepxe uoy tahw etiuq toN"
..." ,denworf I "...sihT"  ".ronam
,yldipar gnitaeb saw traeh yM
"?wonk uoy ,laer yllaer si efil ni gnihton sseuG"  "!ekaf...os
".uoy wonk ylerab I diarfa m'I..."
"!tneve ylimaf a si siht
".rehtie ytic eht ni tcefrep yltcaxe t'nera sgniht ,ees nac uoy sa"
.kcaP eht fo rebmem a t'nsaw noorA dna
.ylsuovren ffo derepmacs eh
,htaehs ym fo eerf pils ot nigeb kcoc ym tlef dna
,rae ym otni denael noorA ",haN"  .derepsihw I
.hguone gnilwoh ton er'uoy ,emit nmad eht lla gnilwoh t'nera uoy fi"
.raer eht tsniaga pmuh kciuq a em evag dna
.kcen eht fo kcab eht no em tib dna
elzzum ym no gnippin yletanoissap
,neht tub ,selur driew fo tol a sah yteicos nabrU"
,ytic eht ni kcab boj ym ekil tol lufwa na leef ot gninnigeb saw sihT
repapdnas sa hguor sa saw eciov siH
gel eht no noorA debbur I
.dehgual kcaP eht fo tser eht sa sdrawkcab leef I dna
,derepsihw I ",tiaw attog eW"
.roolf eht revo lla skroc gnillips dna revo xob eht gnippilf
,woc eht gnilcric sevlow eht was dna
,dezigolopa noorA ",yrros m'I"
2 traP ,xofpoF yb
em dnuora deppils noorA
.yrenecs emas eht fo derit tib a m'I dna ereh yppah eb ot gniog ton er'uoY"  "?!tahW"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”kcaP eht snioJ floW ytiC A“
".yllis tib a smees tI"
.enim tsniaga pu tuons sih desserp dna eromyna tsiser t'ndluoc noorA
",ytic eht ot kcab og ot tnaw t'nod I"
.nirgahc ym ot hcum ,erom neve dum htiw ti gnikac dna ruf kcab ym pu gniffucs ,emas eht did I
.noorA morf gninraw fo drow a htiw
...yawa elim a uoy no ti llems dluoc I"
.gnicar saw traeh yM
"...setsat ruoy htiw yako yltcaxe t'nia su fo tsom dna
pu deffup tlep yM
kcaP ehT denioj dna ytic eht tfel suilenroC ,emit tsaL
,ytic eht ot kcab teg ot ekat dluow ti gnol woh fo tnemecnuonna kciuq a evag dna pu ti detrats revird eht
,lluf-flah saw sub eht nehw dnuorA
,llems gnizilatnat eht etiuq dah tI
"!floW-ytiC emosdnah a htiw dlrow eht gniees dnim t'ndluow I
,derepsihw noorA ,gnilkcuhC
,em gniees nopu dna noisiv fo dleif ym ssorca deklaw rufnooM ,tniop eno tA
sgnittes fo citnamor tsom eht yldrah saw tI
.dnim yna su yap ot mees t'ndid eh tub ,ekoms etteragic fo gnikeer namuh a
"!tnacilppa ,tcepser emos wohS"
.won yllis os demees lla ti
.su ediseb dellor edisyrtnuoc eht sa seye ym gnisolc
?pohs tfig a evah tnalp gniredner krop a dah taht ecalp a t'ndluow yhw
".taht ekil sgniht evorppa ot etov eW" .delims noorA
.taes eht otni swalc sih gud dna
.raewrednu ym tsniaga pu gnisserp
".sreetnulov sa sevlow evif deen ot gniog er'ew"
.dennalp gnihtyreve dah eh
"?!dedaeh ll'ay erehW"
"!llew ffo deyap ti tub tnemirepxe dlob a saw tI
",lleW"    "!SUB EHT POTS"
,sdnats eht ni gnittis stnasaep dna ,seidal ,sdrol fo daetsni tpecxe ,egami doog a evah dluow uoy dna
,daor eht no em dniheb deddap eh sa bmuht sih htiw em gnikcimim
a teg ll'yeht ,raeg labirt eht htiw stun og os ,dworc eht ni sevlow oN"
",hctaw dna ereh tis tsuj uoy ,tnacilppA"
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,flow eht otni denael I dna
.tnempiuqe rof sexob eht hguorht gnilfir nageb tnemhcated siht ni sevlow wollef ehT
lirtson tfel sih fo tuo gnikcits gnirrae enob ekaf a dah flow enO .labirt
?doirep trohs a hcus ni egnahc evislupmi rehtona ekam I dluoc
em gnisaeler erofeb rae ym ni delbmurg flow eht
"!evom ,dnekeew eht yb teem ot atouq a evah ew
,serohc rieht htiw ysub erew sevlow rehto eht elihW
".taht fo tuo kcik
"!SEHCAORPPA AHPLA EHT"
".reeuq t'nia ti sa gnol os dna hctib s'esle enoemos htiw ton s'ti sa gnol os ,cilbup ni tnaw uoy lla tur nac uoy kcaP eht nI
,hgual ot dah I  .pohs tfig A
"?ygolonhcet on ot deneppah tahW"
.emit siht flow dab eht eb uoY" ,dias rufnooM
,ti ssim I fi" ,ti gnilzzun
sredluohs ym dnuora dehcaer eh sa
,xofpoF yb ”kcaP eht snioJ floW ytiC A“
.seye sih otni dekool dna
"!em ot deil egakcap nocab ehT
.seye sih pu derevoc yeht taht yvaeh os erew ecaf sih no selknirw eht dna
.trats hserf a deen htob ew" ,deilper I
"!trevrep ,no evom a teG"  .won enog saw I
liart llams a hguorht dehsup dna
.su ta seson rieht delknirw sexof eht fo wef a dna snamuh eht morf serats wef a tog eW
seldduh gninrom sseltniop eht ta sredro yliad evig dluow reganam elddim a erehw
.dehctiwt dna noitcerid ym ni detniop eson kcalb s'ahplA ehT
sih gniraew elbatrofmocnu yrev dekool noorA .sehtolc elots dna ecnartne eeyolpme s'pohs tfig eht otni kcuns ew
..." ,srotaderp yb dednuorrus saw ehs taht suovren tib tsethgils eht mees t'ndid ohw
.avilas htiw gnippird wam
,bupwerb eht s'ereht neht dnA"
dneffo stnecs s'rehto gnivah ekil t'nod elpoep tsom"
.denrecnoc m'I sa raf sa ti htiw gnorw gnihton t'nia ereht tuB"  .htaehs ym tsniaga pu dehsurb sdap-wap hguoR
dnoces eht saw sihT     .did ylurt I
.mih morf elbuort hguone ni ydaerla saw I
.kcurt pu-kcip a fo wodniw eht fo tuo gninael god wolley a dnif ot ecarbme ruo fo tuo ekorb I
ytisnetni ni gniworg ksum sih llems dluoc I
",ellivneerG :pots txeN"
.nees reve dah I flow gnikool-tneicna tsom eht saw
,uoY"  .dekcip eb ot gnilwoy dna gnikrab
.yaweerf eht otno kcab gnuws dna
em tsniaga gniddorp eson tew s'noorA erongi ot deirt I
.deksa I "?seilppuS"
.elbisiv ylidaer erew stneve eht hcihw morf elohpeep ediw a nepo dils dna
,redluohs ym no wap sih tup noorA
.ruf ym tsniaga gnihsurb htaerb toh sih dna
.tcejbo dluoc I erofeb elzzum eht no em tib yltneg dna
,kcaP eht fo tsdim eht ni em tfel dah noorA  2 fo
!PEEB PEEB  .sih tsniaga eson ym gnisserp yltneg
"?yrewerB hcnaR dlO...did
,gniniatsus-fles deredisnoc si yenom gnikaM"
.pord dluow eohs rehto eht
llew oot ecalp otni tes gnitteg tsuj erew sgnihT
,etag eht dnoyeb tol gnikrap eht ni gnikrul sub ruot gib a fo espmilg a thguac I erehw
woc eht dniheb rood anera eht desolc noorA
slwoh fo surohc a del rufnooM
".seilppus ruo dna sexat dnal eht rof yap spleH"
.detaerc eh gnittes htraE dezilassaV eht ni era hcihw fo ynam
.ti epacse ot gnilggurts nageb I dna
yrotcaf gniredner krop a fo noitcurtsnoc eht gnivorppa su tuoba denrecnoc erom tib elttil a m'I" .denworf noorA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,enihw tfos a esool tel noorA
.hteet rieht otno selttob eniw dlo morf skroc gnikcits nageb sevlow eht sa dekrab rufnooM "!sgnaf ruoy kroc ot erus ekam ,yakO"
".sdnah wen rof gnikool syawla er'yeht ,hcnar eht s'ereht ,lleW"
...hu ,seY"  .dereffo noorA
,doolb gniees ekil t'nod yeht tub tnuh sevlow ees ot ekil stsiruoT
.seert eht morf degreme erugif a erofeb esion gnikaeuqs prahs a draeh I
.ralucitrap ni eno on ot deksa I "?riahcleehw A"
seirossecca citsalp fo seires a no tup dna
.noitartsnomed gnitnuH"
,ecnartne eht dessap eW
"!ereh fo tuo teg stel ,no emoC
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
".emit ym ni sgoh wef a deldnah ev'I" ,delims noorA
ruf rieht otno sgnikram laicaf deroloc ylthgirb no deppals dah sevlow eht fo lla
.senohp-trams rieht gnihsalf dna strihs-t ykcat gniraew stsiruot fo hcnub a dah uoy
",gniht tsrif noitartsnomed gnitnuh a sedulcni taht laed egakcap ,ni gnimoc ruot a evah eW"  ?thgir ,od ot esoppus saw I tahw saw taht os ,ti gniod saw kcaP eht fo tser eht tub ,gniod saw I tahw erus yltcaxe t'nsaw I
.stac ro ,sexof ,snamuh erew stsiruot eht fo tsoM
...did yeht ecnis ni devom evah elpoep gnuoy fo tol a tub ,krow rof gnikool er'yeht fi onnud
.esualppa suorednuht ot
.ecnartne eht morf tuo yrc eciov railimaf a draeh I "!og ,lrig no oG"
.dekrab eciov llirhs a htiw flow llams a
".boj a htiw pu uoy kooh nac ylbaborp yeht reeb tuoba klat uoy sa doog sa krow uoy fi tub ,ereh yug regal
.ahplA gnihcaorppa eht teerg ot srehto eht gninioj dna
deb kcurt eht otni gnuws ylsseltroffe noorA  "!ni no poh"
.sdnalg tnecs s'noorA fo ffo gnitfaw nageb ksum yvaeh A
..." ,eson tew sih tsniaga keehc ym debbur I "...I"
...os ton citsilpmis erom tib a gnihtemos detnaw I..." ,denihw I "...rof
llaw eht tsniaga gnipmuht liat sih raeh dluoc I