.floW-ytiC ,uoy fo dir teg ot gniyrt tsuj ylbaborp saw eh"
,flesym etacilppus ylreporp dluoc I erofeb deppord waj yM
"!tnacilppa na m'I !rotisiv a ton m'I ,hO"
".evil ll'yeht erus er'ew litnu meht eman t'nod eW"  .deksa I
dicnar saw htaerb siH
.nirgahc ym ot hcum ,raer denot-llew sih pu gnirevoc
,deltrohc ehs ",drol ym hO"
,niaga ecno peels s'kcaP eht tpurretni dna pu teg dluoc I erofeB
.desufnoc saw I wonk flow eht tel ot daeh ym gnitlit llits ,derettum I
,revird sub eht ot tcejbo ot deirt I
.saera niatrec ot stifeneb emos dah elytsefil kcaP eht ylraelC
.loohcs yratnemele dednufrednu na ta ecalp fo tuo dekool evah t'ndluow taht thgir eht no elbatrop llams a htiw gnola
"?ygolonhcet oN"  ".ygolonhcet
.kcaP eht fo tser eht yb dewollof yltrohs
ot gniog tsuj m'I..."
detadimitni teg thgim ohw dnuora seiceps rehto ot etairporppani ylbirret dna taht od ot em rof edur ylemertxe neeb evah dluow ti
,weiv otni emac peels ni rehtegot gnildduh sevlow yarg fo riap tsrif ehT
,kcaP eht fo tser eht ot flesym gniraedne no krow dna
.oga seirutnec did sevlow ekil evil ot woh gninrael fo ssecorp eht fo trap lla saw siht wenk I tub
,etrof sih ton saw sgnaf sih gnihsurb taht hteet dewolley sih yb raelc saw ti dna
"!noon litnu cilbup eht ot desolc er'eW"
detrons flow eht ",syad owT"
.eulb reicalg rehto eht dna neerg-evilo eno
?sey ,did sevlow tahw saw siht...tub
.no delkcus gnieb yltnerruc t'nerew taht staet erab reh fo eno hcae ta gnitniop nageb dna nep eht deppord flow-ehs eht ,seye reh gnilloR  "?tol a neppah
.spets eht nwod depael dna
...tub ytic eht ni kcab siht enod reven evah dluow I
",suilenroC ,kcul dooG"  ".uoy knahT"
hguone evian ton saw I tub
.tniop yna ta uoy lepxe nac ew dna
!yenruoj a no gniog saw I ekil tlef I
,ssorca gnimoc saw I drawkwa woh fo erawa ylluf
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
ylreporp noitca yranilpicsid ot gnittimbus ton dna selur kcaP yebo ot gnisufeR
.kcen ym fo kcab eht gnikorts wap sih tlef I sa derepsihw flow eht
.tca yranilpicsid a s'ti ,tca lauxes a ton si kcaP eht fo rebmem tneidebosid a fo raer eht gnipmuH
.rood eht hguorht ylsuovren tuo dekool dna taorht ym deraelc I "...haey ,hU"
"!em eveileb ,ton er'yehT"
.enola erew sevlow wef a hguoht
,thgir eht ot nwod dnuob dluoc I erofeB
kcaP eht erofeb tros yna fo segrahc gnirb tonnac uoy snaem eseht gningiS
!ela ytiurf a naht eniw der enif a htiw ecalp ni erom eb dluow taht egnit ykao ecalp fo tuo ylgnibrutsid a htiw ela trat ylrevo tsom A
,tuo denrut ti ,noitanitsed ym ot ecivres sub ehT    .emoh wen yM
,pu gnikcits liat ym htiw tfel saw I  "!trevrep rehtonA"
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.ecaf s'flow lufhtuoy eht no werg krims A
.dehguoc I dna pu dezies tsehc ym "-oor-
.sgel ym neewteb liat ym dekcut dna ezag ym derewol I "!hO"
.sevlow rehto eht fo ynam ekilnu ,sracs htiw dekramnu dna daorb saw elzzum siH
",rehto hcae teerg kcap eht fo srebmem woh si sihT"
.srepap emos elffuhs ot sbuc eht dnuora gnihcaer
spih gnorts sih tlef I dna elbatrop eht tsniaga smlap ym decarb I ,drawrof em gnihsuP
.tol gnikrap etercnoc a fo pot nO  ...gnidnal dna
.ruf etihw ,tfos ni derevoc dna kciht etiuq saw hcihw ,htaehs sih no dexifsnart yliratnemom saw I ,timda tsum I
.swap ym ni pu delpmurc eruhcorb eht ta nwod kcab neht dna reh ta gnirats ylsuoixna flesym dnuof I dna
ygolonhcet..." ,desuap I "...krow ,sllib ,tneR .ytic eht ni detacilpmoc era sgniht ,lleW"  .deddon noorA  "?efil eritne ruoy ereh devil uoy evaH"
.buc kaew a saw tI
.tserof eht ni eb dluow ew neht dna
"!did srotsecna ym ekil evil ot ekil d'I dna
.tluassa lauxes redisnoc thgim sfloW-ytiC uoy tahw dna
.wonk ton od I ,taht tuoba em llet ot erac ton did revird sub eht yhW
em tsap walc a detniop eH
,elkcac ot nugeb dah ohw ,flow eht morf yawa denrut dna
..." ,raer ym gnipmuh elihw elohw eht
,elytsefil emas eht ni ecno yppah saw I thguoht I" .detcejbo I
.tfel ym ot dekool I dna
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.tluassa lauxes redisnoc thgim sfloW-ytiC uoy tahw
.em morf yawa dednuob ylkciuq dna kcab depmuj rufnooM "!noom eht yB"
".syad owt ni evael ot gniggeb eb ll'uoY"  "!reffid ot geb I"
.elbatrop eht fo ria elats eht ot desopxe saw knuj ym nehw larutan ylgnisirprus tlef tI
,nepo etag eht dellup dna delbmurg flow eht
,tfel eht no htoob tekcit fo riap niwt a gnilaever
,ytic eht ni kcaB
"!ti deen annog er'uoy"
,yrros m'I..." ,dehguoc I "...oD"
",ees I ,ereh tuo drah eb nac efiL"
.smosob detalfni-klim fo swor elpma reh revo gnilwarc zzuf kcalb ni derevoc sbuc ynit eerht htiw flow-
derapmoc trofmocsid fo tib ronim a ylno saw ti tub ,sdap ym no tew dna dloc tlef dnuorg ehT
,ecin dednuos ti thguoht dna kcaP eht tuoba daer I
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ni seert eht hguorht gniog daor devap a deedni saw erehT
,seirots noitcif ecneics yrruf yttums ylsselemahs gnitirw syojne ohw ,xofpoF yb
"...eno rehtona ton ,nooM eht yB"
.erats ot eunitnoc tser eht tub denway flow enO
.kcap eht ni ecalp sih dnif ot seganam suilenroC woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,sriats eht otno gnarps I
"?seman rieht era tahw ,sbuc etuC"
.kcen ym gniffins dna eson sih htiw ni gninael ,wap ym edisa dehsurb eh dna
dehctiwt eson s'flow etihw ehT
!flesym evorp dluow I .yako saw taht
.gnilims ,demialcxe I "!seY"
!recorG s'nasitrA eht ta taem rieht dah ev'I"
!tsrub ot gniog saw I ekil tlef I taht
,tib a em morf yawa detfihs noorA
"!suilenroC si eman yM"
.mraw ti tpek dna
erew shgiht ym neewteb msaisuhtne fo tib detcepxenu ym ot noitcaer siH
..." ,nwod gnittis nageb dna dnuorg eht ta detniop I "...tsuj m'I"
hsurb llat eht hguorht nees flesti ekam ecnef llat a was I nehw depley ylraen I
em deffins eh sa
,etelpmoc etiuq ton saw
,tsirw eht yb em thguac noorA dna flesym gnithgir elihw deppils I sa kcab tohs I
htlif yhcnuar sih fo erom daer nac uoY
,teef ym ot flesym dehsup I
.od ot tahw erus etiuq ton
.dnuorg eht otno gnittips ,flow eht morf yawa flesym dehsup dna depley I
elbatrop eht fo tuo deppoh tuoba tsuj I
"...hu...guns...ot stnaw enoyna fi...hu...ereh nwod yal
",sgoh yb netae ,selsaem ,repmetsid ,repmetsiD"
.deddon I  "?dengis uoY"
"...won peels ot og...hu ot gniog m'I"
.daeh ym detlit I "?em nodraP"
;dedulcni flesym ,senohpllec rieht ot dehcatta s'enoyreve
!tseuq ym ni epoh dewener em evag siht dna
.wollof ot em denokceb dna
.sih ni wap ym gnidloh
,ffits saw liat siH
".tahw uoy llet I ,hguoht nocab doog nmad ekaM
,gib a was I ,ylwols gninruT
,yllanretni decniw yltnatsni dna dnuorg eht dettap I
,tnemom taht litnU
.redle na hcum yrev si eno tnerruc ruo dna kcap eht fo rebmem tsedle eht era sahplA
.staet reh ta delkcus yeht sa gninihw nageb sbuc eht dna denepo ylizal seye s'flow eht ,gnitronS
taht seoD" ,pil ym tib I
pu mraw ot nageb ti tub eson ym delkcit ruf siH
"?wonk uoy ,efil relpmis a
"!taht ekil em eracs t'nod dna daor nmad eht esu ,lleh gnikcuF" .em ta elttips gnikcilf ,swaj sih deppans flow eht
.eruhcorb eht fo pot eht ta dias tI
,tsaerb tsal eht ot detniop ehs
.detrons flow etihw eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
"?ereh uoy era yhw ,oS"
,evil ot desu sevlow yaw eht sdrawot kcab
..." ,etag tnorf ,llat eht dehctalnu flow eht sa derutnev I "...oS"
?ti eganam kcaP eht did woh
desiar selkcah yM
:taeper I"  "?!tluassa lauxeS"
!5102 fo remmuS eht ni edam noinU gniwerB tnednepednI enipluV taht nosiaS hcaeP taht naht esrow detsat ti
.noissergga fo yalpsid a hcus yb
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,won em dniheb erew sgniht hcuS
.em sdrawot ylnmelos gnirats sevlow dekan owt fo tra railimaf eht ffo gniwohs ,eruhcorb eht tuo denettalf I "!sey ,hO"
denworf I  ...floW ytiC
,uoy llet em tel dna htuom ym fo edisni eht dekcil eh nehw sitivignig eht etsat yllacitcarp dluoc I
,kcab og ot saw
,seerht fo spuorg ro sriap ni gnipeels erew tsoM
.spih eht yb em debbarg dna
",evael uoy neht dna syad owT"
,pu doots I dna nwod erutangis tsal ym dehctarcs I tnemom eht pu sdrow esoht demit ehS
.eman sih gnicnuonorp nehw lwoh thgils a tuo tel flow eht ",noorA s'eniM"
.eneigyh latned retteb htiw rebmem a yllaedi
".sevlow gnipeels eht dnif uoy litnu thgiarts gniog peek dna gnivael retfa thgir nruT
,trid htiw ykcits dna tew tlef ruf yM
,detrons ehs ",hpmh ,rufnooM"
!gnitarogivni etiuq saw tserof eht hguorht klaw eht ,yaw rehtiE
,rae ym fo esab eht dehctarcs swalc sih nehw enihw tfos a otni denrut ylkciuq taht tub ,tib a delbmurg I
,rufnooM htiw retnuocne elttil etanutrofnu taht retfa ytniatrecnu dna yteixna fo tib a deniater llits I hguohT
.ytic eht ni saw I erehw yppah t'nsaw I..."
",denigami I tahw etiuq t'nsi sihT"
.yawrood nepo eht otni depmuj dna
.trid eht otno tuo em dessot dna kcen eht fo ffurcs eht yb pu em dekcip tub lla eh dna
.noitalumits eht morf ffits elttil a nworg dah
.deffuh flow etihw eht "!og tsuJ"
,redluohs eht ni em dehcnup noorA ,gnihguaL
.sub eht no em ot txen gnittis sseflow dega-elddim eht sdrawot dna nroc fo sdleif gnillor eht morf yawa dekool I dna
nus gninrom ylrae eht ni denetsilg ruf yarg siH
.tuons sih ssorca morf em ta nwod gnikool
.daeh ym fo tuo eniw enif dna reeb tfarc fo sthguoht hcus tup ot tseb ym deirt I
?gnithgif yalP ?gnilwoH
tsehc ym ni hcum os pu dellew noitapicitna ym dna ,selim eht nwod gnitnuoc
.htiw sdneirf saw I snamuh eht fo ynam dluoc os tub
!uoY semocleW kcaP ehT
..." ,tnorf eht ni hteet gnissim ynam gnilaever
pu sedahs reh dehsup sseflow ehT
etihW suilenroC si eman yM"
.tuo wap ym dleh I
.ygolonhcet on htiw efil elpmis a evil dna kcaP eht nioj ot gniog m'I .won ma I ereh tub
..." ,taorht ym deraelc I "...I"
.smuhc ym htiw sbupwerb doohrobhgien ym ta reeb decirprevo htiw ylleb ym taolb I dluow erom on
,flow laer a eb ot gniog saw I
"?floW-ytiC ,ereh uoy
dloc saw eson yM
thgir ym ,gnihtyna ssecorp dluoc I erofeB
?tsrif od ew od tahw..."
,deneppah ti sa ,hcihw
,teef sih ot depmuj noorA dna
".htlaeh latnem dna lacisyhp ruoy rof ytilibisnopser yna morf eerf er'ew dna
,kcaP eht ta devaw yldrawkwa I
eson ym dehcaer ti litnu
.elpuoc floW-ytiC a ot dlos"
?si enohpllec a tahw wonk won uoy od
.noislupxe ni tluser lliw
.og ot dednetni I erehw morf yawa selim eerht doog a gnidne
"...hteet wolley ,ruf etihw..."
"!ereh evil ot tnaw I
elbatrop eht fo edis eht tsniaga gninael
,regnarts a htiw gnola gnis ot tnaw t'ndid yeht spahreP
,nway a ni denepo ylizal wam reh "...thgiR"
.htuom ym fo foor eht ta gnippal
elzzum ym fo edis eht gnola deliart eson tew sih sa delggig I
eno siht piks nac uoy
,ksum ycips a htiw dna yhtraE
,eugnot sih htiw nepo htuom ym decrof eh dna
,srepap elffuhs ot deunitnoc ehs "...huh hU"
.meht nioj og ,snommoc eht ni gnippan si kcaP ehT"  .won emoh saw I
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.sregnis eht ecnelis tub gnihton od ot demees
"!dloc a daerps ot yaw doog a s'tahT"
"?!gniod uoy era lleh eht tahW"
"!tuo pord ton llahs I"
"!ahplA eht morf sredro no ereh ,etihW suilenroC tnacilppA"
,won rettam t'ndid ti tuB
steehs nottoc enilef tnuoc daerht derdnuh evif ym rednu ti deppils evah dluoc I
"-eb tsum siht ,yrros m'I
.trihs deralloc-llat ym ffo worht dna snaej rengised ym fo tuo ymmihs ot gnihsur
.emit tsal nwot eht no tuo tnew ew nehw flow draug yldneirf gib rieht em dellac yehT
".tnacilppa na m'I...hu ,m'I ,olleH"
,seert gnirewot yb dednuorrus saw I
”kcaP eht snioJ floW ytiC A“
,liart trid eht hguorht yaw eht detniop sngis gnikiH
",gningis ytilibaiL"  "?spahrep ,gnitnuH
.enip fo llems teews eht ni gnihtaerb ,deffins I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.spil ym gnikcil morf flesym pots ton dluoc I tub yteixna ym edih ot deirt I
.sreviaw ytilibaiL"
"?ahplA yas tsuj uoy did..."
em dnuora gniws flow eht ,tnatsni na nI
"!hguone riaf ,llew ,thgirlA"
dleif eht ni tuo gnar lwoh gnicreip A
dne dluow nroc eht nooS
derab erew sgnaf dewolley siH .flow etihw
.nroc fo swor sseldne eht ni flesym esol ot tseb ym gniyrt
".floW ytiC ,evila uoy tae annog er'yeht"
won litnu edir ruoh eerht eritne eht no drow a dias t'ndah ehS
.tsehc sih otni ecaf ym thguorb dna
ekil uoy revenehw evael ot eerf er'uoy ,tnacilppa na er'uoy elihW"
dna elbatrop eht tsniaga gninael llits
ti gnihguor fo dnof erew sdneirf ym fo emos yhw ees ot gnitrats saw I
",ti ot desu teg ll'uoY"
drawrof og ot yaw tseb eht tlef I
.gnitarelihxe etiuq saw tnecs sih dna
".siht tpecca dna ngis uoy sselnu tnacilppa na sa ni uoy tel t'now eW
.eliforp yrrufoS sih no
".taht naht regnol tsal annog ton er'uoy" ,dehsal liat sih
"...huh hU"  "!gnihtyreve rof uoy knahT"
.seye eulb dehsinotsa htiw em ta derats dna
era yhW"  -fo elttob ecin a ekilnu ton
...redro na uoy evig setamkcap ruoy nehW"
ecnef eht sdrawot gniklaw nageb flow ehT
.gnilbmur kciht a fo dnuos eht ta dehctiwt rae
!tsiruot a ton m'I"
,sgnaf etihw-ylraep sih ffo gniwohs ,dennirg noorA
.hctorc sih ta dehctarcs yllausac dna
.detcartsid regnol on saw I dnoces eht tuo detrulb I "?huH"
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.tib a ni tuo dnif ll'uoy ,lleW"
.denihw yeht nehw sbuc reh fo eno gnittap yllanoisacco
.sgniht esoht htiw tontahw dna serutcip ruo gnikat ,yad yreve ereh gnimoc stsiruot teg eW"
.delims I dna teef ym ot em depleh flow yarg ehT
.gniprihc drib fo sdnuos eht dna ,sehsub gniltsirb
".ot tnaem erew ew woh
.deppots ylneddus rufnooM  "!netsil uoy..."
"-thgim uoy kniht I" .deksa noorA
"!ahplA ,seY"  "!OG"  "-di on dah I"
,emoh kcab saw I fI .truh ti dna
..." ,gnissim saw erofeb morf flow ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,ria eht otni semuf gnihcleb srac ynam ooT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.gnidnal eht otno tsrif-tuons gnillaf dna pets a htaeneb seot ym gnihctac
.eb dluohs ti sa nevlow sa yltcaxe ton saw eson ym ,eurt saw tI
,drawrof riahc reh dellor ehS
".yresim sih fo tuo mih tup ,esiwrehto mih netae evah dluow I
enodnu yletelpmoc saw dah edun gnieb noitacilpmi lauxes revetahW
,seirujni detaler gnitnuh ,sdnuow walc ,gnitib ot tcejbus eb thgim uoy ,ereh elihW
.gnillaf morf em gnippots
,ti gnillems yb tsuj 9102 a dna ceblaM evorG radeC 8102 a neewteb ecnereffid eht llet dluoc I
.em ta nwod gnireep saw eh dna
em tsniaga smra sih depparw
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tniop siht ta em ekil yltcaxe t'ndid eh ezilaer ton ot
.rood elbatrop eht ot pu gnidael sriats nedoow ytekcir eht ot detniop dna
,em ta daeh sih gnikahs ahplA eht derongi
.ecnelis ni em ta gnirats deunitnoc yehT
hsub a hguorht gnipael
”kcaP eht snioJ floW ytiC A“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,teef ym ot delbmarcs I sA
,gnirettalf yltcaxe ton
"?wonk'y ,keew a retfa tuo pord klof tsoM"
...ereh thgir...hu...haeY"
.meht fo ffo decnuob nus eht sa gniralg sessalgnus kciht reh ,detrons ehs
,rednu edih ot ereh steehs hcus on erew erehT
,gninrom eht ni ylrae siht snrecnoc ym niatretne ot doom on ni saw ohw namuh deye-yggab a
"...dap dneirf on...hu ro...dap rolehcab ym...ereh
.tnemeticxe fo lluf efil a eb noos dluow tahw ot
delrans flow eht "!oG"
2 fo 1 traP ,xofpoF yb
"?yako ,tuo pord uoy erofeb em ees emoC
.kniht I ,su deniur sah
.sevlow fo spuorg rehto eht htiw gnola
,em ot txen dnuorg eht otno despalloc ot degnoleb ti flow ehT
”kcaP eht snioJ floW ytiC A“   :yojne esaelP
"?wonk 'y ,klof ynnuf adniK"
.flow gnisrun ,gnilaeppanu yllauxes yrev a fo ynapmoc eht ni ti gniod yb
.elpoep tsom rof t'niA"
,hctorc ym pu tlef wap yvaeh sih neht dna
,rufnooM ,flow etihw eht deciton I
,dehctamsim erew seye sih dna
ruf ym tsniaga hsurb htaerb toh sih tlef I
.edis eht ot daeh sih detlit noorA
"!ereht yalpsid a ta dah yeht haryS fo ssalg tnellecxe na htiw llew deriap nocab doow-elppa riehT
edisa rufnooM tup ot dediced I ,oS
,yldas hcihw ,gniwolleb nwo ym htiw rovaf eht nruter ot detpmetta I dna
.ti revo yltsom saw I
.yawa deps ti sa sub eht fo ediskcab eht ta ylpeed gnilworg ,delrans I
,sdoow eht hguorht tsrub I dna
"!uoy sdnammoc...ahplA...ruoY"
.ssa ym tsniaga pu dnirg
.detaerc eh gnittes htraE dezilassaV eht ni era hcihw fo ynam
.etiteppa rof ssensuovren fo noisserpxe nevlow siht ekatsim ot dnuora snamuh on erew ereht ,yllufknahT
,kcen eht no kcab eht no em deppin dna ni denael eh sa delworg tsehc sih "...redro
.nwod eman ym gnihctarcs nageb I
.floW ytiC emos ton
ehs gnipeels ,esebo na fo thgis thguac I nehw
"?yawyna ,gnidrager eseht era tahW"
"?ti weiv sredistuo uoy woh taht sI"
.meht pota nep a gnitnalp erofeb em fo tnorf ni srepap fo seires a deppals ehs
.em ta gnirats erew seye tnereffidni fo sriap sseltnuoc dna pu detlit ylizal sdaeh riehT
.pu delruc dna ssarg pmad-wed eht otno nwod flesym derewol I ,ylwolS
",eseht evah ew yhw s'taht dnA"  .derepsihw I
".em ot hguone yppah mees yehT
hA"  .kcab deilper I "?nur-hA"
".noitca yranilpicsid ecaf ro won thgir ffo ekat ot deen lliw uoy hcihw ,sehtolc fo esu eht sedulcni siht dna ygolonhcet devorppa-non yna esu ton yam uoY
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,xofpoF yb
.won flow eurt a saw I
.tnereffid flesym deredisnoc yllaer t'ndah I
hA"  .erom tib a lwoh eht dezisahpme eh ",noooor-
ybraen tuo gnar slwoh fo seires A
".noos emityna stsiruot ot sredro tuo gnivig ton s'eH
.tuons ym morf ssorca trid eht ni dednal wap-toof yarg a