elfir eht htiw gniyalp nwatfeT fo stohs lareves koot dna
.delims feT ”,sruoy s’ti dna
.rewop ycnegreme tub gnihtyreve tsol evah ot raeppa eW“
eciwt tes dna esir 4 nedlaV gnihctaw ,detiaw yehT
,ria eht detset dna
.liat sih no thgir noil eht desnes dna
.morf gninnur neeb dah eh htrae no tahw gnirednow ,smra sih otni detlem kraM dna
,edisa tesdaeh reh no enohporcim moob eht dehsup aroL
,riaf saw aroL sa krad sa nexiv a dna dnoces snoitacinummoc ,nasuS
.mih derewsna kraM
,derednow nasuS ”...tuB“
:sarbez fo dreh a dnuof yeht
”.tuo gnitrats erofeb hcnul doog a evah ot tnaw yam uoy os ,regaem ytterp si edivorp yeht doof liart eht raeh I
”?ffuts neerg taht ekil yllaer uoY“
aroL ta dekniw dna
.sevooh s’kraM tsniaga yal dne detfut eht taht os
”.dewap erab ssenredliw eht ni thguac eb ot esufer I
.yldetaeper ti fo denraw neeb dah yehT
,lio evilo dna daerb htiw dalas egral yrev a dah kraM
”?yawyna ,morf edam ffuts taht si tahW“
.deraeppa rewsna ehT
,sruoh owt ni eerf eb ll’I“ .deddon dna
.gnisuap ,dedda eh
,arreT dlO morf seicepS
”.ti gnikam truh saw gnihton dna ,ti tae ot evah t’nod uoY“
.swap gib esoht ni swalc rozar eht derebmemer kraM dna
,enam dna liat sih tuo koohs dna
hteet reh gniyalpsid
”.slrig xof ni si eh naht syob arbez ni detseretni erom ylsuoivbo s’eh
.deerga eh ”,ti eb yam tahT“
”.esaelp ,kraM em llaC
s’erehT .tahw tuo erugif t’nac I tub
”,retsamkcod ,krow ruoy ot uoy evael ll’I“
.neht erudecorp noitcefnisid a htiw daeha og ll’eW“
,denruter noitalucric ria fo ssih tfos eht dna
,deksa gnieb tuohtiw meht dniheb tuhs trop eht dils feT
”,ainoeL eht htiw nwatfeT“
.eerga ot dah kraM
.tnemucod eht gnidaer tuohtiw dengis niatpac noil ehT
ecudorp larutlucirga rehto dna niarg tuo gniyrrac ro sdoog derutcafunam ni gnignirb
”?deneppah evah ot smees yltcaxe tahW
.devirra werc feiler eht ,retal setunim wef A
.wonk ot detnaw kraM
”,esraps dna thgit era remmiks a no sretrauQ“
.noihsaf gnisuma na ni eson sih gnilknirw
”,gnirettahc era hteet ruoY .kraM ,tsrif knird mraw a dnif oG
”.etsat eht esiugsid ot gnihtemos htiw denosaes eb dluoc ti tsael ta tuB“
.daeh liart eht ot tropsnart ypmub rehtona koot dna
,reciffo snoitacinummoc sih ot moor eht ssorca dekool eH
.depeeb rotacinummoc tekcop sih dna
.arreT no kcab sraey derdnuh ruof revo rof sarbez nopu srotaderp neeb t’nevah snoiL“
.rehtie noissim lamrof a no ereh ton m’I
.erom on od dluoc eh thguoht eh nehw deeps sih pu dekcip dna
.syab gnikcod eht drawot dna sretrauq gnipeels eht dna spo morf yawa
.erutseg fo daorb dna ,etiteppa fo egral
.tenalp gnicudorp niarg a saw nedlaV ecnis
,noitats eht fo mir eht dnuora noitcerid rehto eht ni deunitnoc kraM
.sredro rieht koot dna devirra retiaw A
.eugnot reh htiw gnisaet dna
.ratS s’nedlaV rof thgir dedaeh dna tibro yratenalp edisni yaw pmuj eht fo tuo emac I tub
.retupmoc s’ainoeL ot senil citsongaid eht dekooh ew retfa yltrohs tih melborp ehT
”?tnecs ddo taht saw tahW
.nasuS ta dekool eH
”.uoy rof remraw eb dluohs tahT“
,nwatfeT llems dluoc eh taht ,ylerus ,denigami eh ,tcaf nI
.krad tnew dna derekcilf sthgil eht ,ylper a htiw pu emoc dluoc kraM erofeB
.esruoc fO .acsaC ot suissaC“ .dias eh
,hsurb dna kcor fo elbmut a drawot ,edis eht ot denrut eH
,reenigne deifilauq ylluf ylno rieht yllautca saw ohw
.ylsuovren dehgual dna
”,ytisrevinu eht ta eno desu I“
kcab emac noitats eht fo srodirroc krad eht morf sgnileef eht
,ecap sih denekciuq arbez ehT
”.ffats no hcet retupmoc doog a evah uoy epoh I“
.deerga eh ”,doog sllemS“
.retne dna edisa latrop eht edils ot esaeler launam eht desu yeht dna
.enam yvaeh nwo sih hguorht thgir
.worbeye na desiar kraM
,retemonorhc s’kraM yb setunim 51 ylno saw tub ,ega na ekil demees tahw retfA
.ylihtoot gninnirg dna
.ereh elosnoc eht no tpmorp a htiw stlah neht dna
.snoitareneg fo elpuoc a rof sedacsaC eht dna aiepoissaC neewteb seitilitsoh neeb evah ereht wonk uoY
.deksa ehs ”?ereht si are taht morf gnivivrus hcum toN“
,naidacsaC ,I dluoc
.ylper eht saw ”,esnopser a stcepxe tI
.notliM ro elbiB eht ton dna ,hguoht ,eraepsekahS ylbaborp s’ti kniht I
,yrt dnoces eht litnu hctac t’ndid ti dna edirrevo launam eht tih I
.gninnips saw daeh s’kraM dna ,llems rehtael eht fo lluf demees moor ehT
”.ti tpecca ll’uoy epoh I dna
”llaC fo troP esolC A“:yojne esaelP
.denway dna daeh reh koohs lrig xof ehT .deksa kraM
.ereh sraey owt ym gnirud erofeb reveN“
”,ti yojne os ,won sruoy s’tI
,mih revo tperc dah taht gnileef ddo eht morf gninekawaer ,deknilb kraM
,eno ekil thguoht
,dnoces a ylno rof derats feT
,eno ekil devom eH
lla s’tI .emag fo sessalc dna srebmun suoirav gnitoohs dna gniklats rof dedrawa era seihporT
,smra sih ni ylisae kraM denrut dna
.daerb dna dalas eht ot flesmih deilppa kraM
,niaga ni desolc leef ot nageb eh
.reh dniheb desolc rood gnidils eht gnihsup
.uoy tae ot gniog ton m’I“
”,aedi oN“ .deggurhs ohw
”.elbatrofmoc erom leef ll’I dna niatpaC fo daetsni feT em llaC
ssenfoola rieht rof deton erew stnadnecsed eninoel ehT
,elbatrofmocnu leef mih edam taht ,nosaer emos roF .deksa eh
.ti no eraepsekahS fo skrow etelpmoc eht ,sgniht rehto gnoma ,sah taht ainoeL eht no nibac ym ni redaer tekcop a evah I
.yrt a ti evig ot ekil d’I
.noissimmoc ylno sih eb ot deraeppa
,won elbisiv saw htaerb rieht taht dezilaer kraM dna
,dias ehs ”,erom yna peels
yart sih gnikat erofeb liatkcoc eciuj elbategev a dna ,daerb mraw
,ecnelis saw erehT
,ylesnemmi flesmih gniyojne saw noil ehT
ro sotohp toohs rehtie nac dna ,dewolla era srotisiV
.roolf eht fo leetsalp eht no gnikaeuqs selos pils-non rebbur sih
”.oga sraey ytnewt litnu pu erew yeht tub ,lortnoc enirdnaeL rednu regnol on era sedacsaC ehT“ .ylwols dias eh
”.tey gnitaucave trats ot deen oN“ .dias boR
.niatpac gib eht dna mih neewteb ksed eht gnittup
,mih tsurt ot detnaw kraM
”,niatpaC ,ereh melborp ciffart a evah yllausu t’nod eW“
.knil eht revo emac eciov s’regdab ehT
,reh ta sulyts sih ssot ot denetaerht kraM sa
dnuora delruc liat siH
.tsehc dna sredluohs ralucsum revo won gnidaerps enam yvaeh sih
.ti no gnikrow llitS“
.4 nedlaV tuoba kraM ot klat ot ekil d’I
”.era snoitpure egnarts eseht sa lufraef dna ,nworg suoigidorp tey ;noitca lanosrep ni ,em ro ,flesyht naht reithgim on nam A“
.derewsna retsamkcod eht ”,noitacinummoc ro snoitavreser fo dnik yna fo sretsam era yehT
,daeh sih gnikahS
,letoh troser niam eht ot daor fo selim fo elpuoc a revo depmub taht
krowtra dna gnitirw sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,gnihtemos gninnur dna evil llits si metsys ruO
.ti tuoba kniht t’nod dna ffuts siht ot desu era su fo tsoM
,yas thgim uoy tahw rettam oN
sih gniyas ,ecivres retupmoc rof degassem dah
.duol tuo dehgual
.dlrowemoh namuh eht no noitatnemirepxe cihprom ot dne na tup sraw eneg eht erofeb kcab
.dnoces a rof rotinom knalb eht ta derats dna
.ti deen I won dna“ ,dias eh
,srethgierf edart yb pu edam saw ciffart tsoM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,tekcaj s’rotisiv eht ekorts dna tuo hcaer ot erised ehT
.deddon eh yllaniF
”.erofeb meht nees ev’I esruoc fO .aroL ,ytisrevinu ta senirdnaeL erew erehT“
.ni deklaw yeht sa ylmlac pu dekool dna lenap eht ta saw
gnihtemos saw ti mih dlot niarbdnih siH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.gnilims ,deddon feT
,latipac naidacsaC eht ni smetsys tnemnrevog eht nwod tuhs ot desoppus saw mrow ehT
”.gniht fo tros taht ,ycarip ,ecnerefretni edart tub ,erafraw nepo toN
”,resolc teg dna meht klats s’teL“
”.htrow ’semulov dnasuoht ruof tsomlA“ .dias eh
,gniksa tuoba suovren fi sa noitisop sih detfihs nwatfeT
.gnimoc saw thguoht eh tahw rof flesmih eraperp ot deirt dna
si yrots s’yadot dna
.noitcaretni na neeb evah yam erehT
dexaler tsomla dah eh dna
,ciahcra thgirnwod sdnuoS“
?morf emoc taht did erehw ,tiaW
.emit fo doirep gnol a hcus retfa rednuht ekil dednuos taht esion etihw htiw ecnelis eht gniteknalb
,thgin lufdaerd siht ekil tsom nam a eeht ot eman
.psarg mraw tub feirb a ni
”.yllufecrof ti od ot pu siht tes dna
.flesmih llet ot detnaw eh ”,suolucidir si sihT“
.ecafrus eht morf pu delttuhs eb ot niarg fo daol a rof gnitiaw rethgierf ytpme na saw rehto ehT
.esruoc fO“ .demialcxe feT ”!tiaW“ .dednopser nasuS
”,dooG“ .dereetnulov eh
”.pleh dluow eseht fo eno ebyaM“ .dennirg eh
kcalb dna tpek llew syawla erew yeht hguoht
’dnah nwo sih yb ainoliuqA fo gniK‘ ti eviG“
,ylthgirb deksa orrub eht
elbat eht rednu kcoltef s’kraM dnuof toofwap a fo sdap tfos ehT
.meht rof htoob etavirp dna tnasaelp a detaitogen ylhtooms noil eht erehw
no kcab emac sthgil eht nehw yaw rieht no llits erew dna ,ylwols gnivom
.elttil a uoy wonk ydaerla I .uoy ekil I tuB“
dreh eht taht derevocsid nwatfeT elihw
.ria on ,sthgil oN“
.demialcxe eh ”!nmaD“
metsys edacsaC eht ot aiepoissaC morf etuor ne stnemucod naol dna stnemeerga edarT
:ti deticer ohw ,kraM ot ylesoidnarg derutseg dna wob a edam feT
mih no ni gnisolc erew sllaw eht fi sa
.enil eht no gnireenigne dah ehs ecno
.dehgual feT dna ,elbat eht no tes saw taem fo etalp eht nehw eson sih delknirw arbez ehT
devired neeb dah seneg lartsecna s’kraM hcihw morf
,mih rewsna dluoc gnireenigne erofeb dna
.rettahc mmoc detaicossa dna sthgil gnihsalf lausu eht htiw
.smetsys retupmoc dna rewop lluf tuohtiw setunim ytriht dna sruoh owt won saw tI .dias eh
.sgel reh dnuora delruc liat reh htiw loots reh no tcere tas dna
.rood eht rof dedaeh dna
.yllautca ,kniht thgim uoy naht eroM“
.seye sih gnisolc ,daeherof sih debbur kraM
.srotaderp yllaer reven erew shprom noil dnA
.egde no ydaerla erew sevren s’kraM tub ,gnisselb a neeb evah dluow tI
.ylfeirb mih gnitcartsid
”,ris ,seY“ .deksa eh
.selggig fo tif a htiw nekat saw aroL
.elims elttil a htiw ,aroL drawot niaga deddon eH
” ,raseaC suiluJ morf s’tI“
seiceps narreT ,lanigiro eht
.mih dniheb llits saw ohw ,nwatfeT otni pmub ot ylno ksed nwo sih drawot drawkcab pets a koot dna dias kraM ”,dooG“
.tropweiv doog a dah eh dna
,lenap noitacinummoc eht ta nexiv eht ot wob elttil a edam eH
,mih rof ecnegludni erar a
.4 nedlaV fo tnenitnoc nrehtuos eht no ylhtooms dednal elttuhs ehT
raeg latner rieht pu dekcip yeht hcnul retfA
”.pleh ruoy rof sknahT
,sepirts s’enirbeZ eht gnitnuoc erew eh fi sa dekool tI
.etamitigel erew yeht derugif I os
”,ereht nwod tuhs si gnihtyrevE
.retemonorhc tsirw sih ta dekool kraM
?egnarts os taht sI“
.ylknalb mih ta derats snexiv ehT
.ti niard dna erutcnup ot efinktleb prahs a decudorp dna
”,yrotsih ni rehtona dna ycamolpid ni ronim lluf a koot I“
.ylwols ti dekorts dna
.tnemesuma fo ria na htiw ,deksa eh
.eman eht dezingocer kraM neht dna
.yawa raf ton sessarg eht hguorht gniltsur feT ot gninetsil ,flesmih dih dna
”?boR ,sutatS“ dias ylpmis kraM ,derewsna boR nehW
”...ssecca retupmoc yna tuohtiw tuB“ .dias eh
yletaidemmi feT .tpmorp emas taht kcab gnivig speek tsuj ti ,od ew tahw rettam oN
,ytsat ylriaf saw daerb ehT
yttap taem noitatimi sih dehsinif feT
,snottub owt desserp eH
.gniod er’ew tahw wonk boR teL“
,sredluohs sih morf tekcaj rehtael eht devomer ylitsah dna dehsulb eH
riahc sih ni tas eH
ria gnitalucricer troppus efil fo ssih tfos ehT
.dednuos emihc ytimixorp eht nehw lanimret sih morf pu dekool enitraP kraM retsamkcoD
os ro sretem derdnuh eht revoc ot reverof ekat ot demees tI
”,tib a deyaled eb yam sriaper ruoy ekil skooL“
.flesmih dniheb hctah eht demmals dna denruter feT
.gnilims ,dias ehs
.dellik yllautca erew slamina oN
dna draob ym revo lla pu gnimoc erew smrala ehT
.meht dlot regdab eht
.mih dlot noil eht
”.seog esnepxe sa raf sa taert yM
.tcepser dna pihsdneirf fo erutseg lanoitidart eht ni dnah sih dereffo neht
”,kraM ,erofeb noil a nees reven dah uoy kniht d’uoY“
,gniraor dna dehtuom nepo
,yltfos gniksa erofeb ,erom ecno arbez eht dessik eH
.tnemesuma ni eugnot knip
.niatpaC ,llib riaper ruoy ot dedda stiderc derdnuh a ylno s’tI“
redluohs sih revo dekool eH
”.retteb eno siht ekil I tuB“ .dias eh
”?rewop ycnegreme no rof doog ew era gnol woH“
,kraM depolevne tnecs rehtael eht fo duolc a dna
.pacitnedi sih gnireffo dna kraM ot gninrut erofeb
.sexof owt eht ta dennirg niatpac noil ehT
”.gnitarepo evreserp eht peek ot og sdnuf eht tub ,yecirp rehtar
.mih ot gnittespu etiuq saw rac dnuorg eht fo gnitloj eht esuaceb ylthgil netae dah eh dalg saw kraM
.retnuh yalp ot selfir resal laiceps esu
”.retal ti ezylana nac ew os ydaerla derutpac pmud a evah I
nwatfeT .gnirewoprevo tsomla saw lairetam ddo eht leef ot
.yawa mih evig dluow enola ti fo dnuos eht erus saw eh dna
.seye s’kraM ot ssenkcalb latot ekil demees tahw otni gnihsinav dna gniwollof liat sih ,pu spets eerht
”.segdab eseht esu tsuJ
”.sseug I gnihtemos tae attoG“
.ylluftnevenu dessap tfihs eht fo tser ehT .ekiltrad
.lla ta enilef a ekil ton
,knalf sih no swalc s’feT ro
keehc s’kraM dehcnip nwatfeT dna
”?metsys ruoy ni gniod ti s’tahW
,kcab sih depolevne ydob regral s’nwatfeT fo thgiew yvaeh eht nehw
.steehs elur eht dna ,spam ruoy era ereH“
”,sepirtS ,no emoc hO“
.ti od nac aroL ro nasuS“
.thgir er’uoY .feT ...ypoc ruoY“
3 enecS ,VI tcA ,snehtA fo nomiT ,eraepsekahS mailliW—
,deneppah dah tahw denialpxe noil ehT
.deworroB“ .dias eh
.dias feT ”,eruS“ ”?neht
.noil eht nioj ot
.sredluohs s’kraM dnuora nwod gnah enam sih gnittel
.egdab DI on htiw dik a yb dereviled erew stekcap citamolpid detpyrcne esohT .retteb wenk I“
.sneerg sih otno emos detriuqs dna
”.tsetal eht ta yrutneC ht71 eb thgim ti gnisseug m’I“ .reh dlot kraM
edirrevo launam eht etarepo feT tel dna ,decseiuqca eH
.erom ecno tcarter neht dna
”...em tae ot gniog t’nsaw eh dias neve eH
,saw eh erehw gnittegrof
”.yrutneC hteitnewT .arreT tneicnA
,tros emos fo htorb ebyam ro aet fo puc a gnisrun saw eH
esnopser tcerroc eht su llet uoy lliW“
”,noitats llams a si sihT“
,boj eht od ot selttuhs ograc 61 tuoba koot tI
.tih hcae fo rebmun laires eht sdrocer elfir eht dna hsalf resal a ot dnopser taht srebmun laires htiw deggat era efildliW
.elzzum sih fo pan etihw trohs eht hguorht elbisiv ylisae ,dehsulb yllautca arbez ehT .delkcuhc ehs
sregnif s’retsamkcod eht revo ylthgil tfird wap sih tel eH
kool knalb a meht gnivig saw nasuS
.dias I tahw tnaem I“
,delims nwatfeT ”.og ll’I
,nwatfeT ta dekool enoyrevE
.spihs thgie rof gnikcod dah ylno dna
.dluohs ti sa ,yllacitamotua meht rof nepo dils snoitarepo ot rood ehT
.neddibrof erew ,sevink gnidulcni ,snopaew lla esuaceb ,derats kraM
.derit yltsuj eht fo peels eht tpels dna ,eta yehT
.yttap yos eht ot yllarebil deilppa eh hcihw
.dluoc eh sa ylteiuq sa gnitnap
.sedacsaC eht ot refer ot detresni neeb evah tsum ,esruoc fo ,naidacsaC“ .derumrum eh
,yad lluf driht eht no ylno saw tI
gnisserd dalas fo reniatnoc a deppacnu eH
,daerb derefforp eht gnitpeccA ”.doog etiuq s’tI
”.em ot esnes yna ekam t’nseod tI“
reh ot egassem citpyrc eht ffo daer kraM
egreme ot swalc ekil-rozar gniwolla
”.taht fo tuo teg ot sedirrevo ruoy esu ot elba erew uoy dalg m’I
.daeh sih gnisiar ,dias kraM
.tnedive yrev saw noitartsurf s’regdab ehT
.ecaps ni reerac laer a evah ot detnaw eh fi stcnitsni lufraef sih edirrevo ot nrael ot dah eh taht dediced neht dna
,gninepo eht otni debmilc feT dna
”llaC fo troP esolC A“
,ssik eht ekorb yehT
”?erutaretil tneicna fo naf a er’uoY“
deleehw serutaerc depirts erom ro derdnuh a fo dreh eht ,eno sa tsomlA
enitraP“ .ti denepo dna tuo ti dellup eH
”,doog yllautca ton fi ,elbarelot s’taht ,lleW“
,stoober retupmoc ehT“
a tuo gnikcits ,deksa eh
,mih rof thgiarts gninnur feT was dna
,deifirreT .liava on ot tub
”.noitats detaehnu na rof edam t’nsaw mrofinu taht dnA
.ti tuoba draeh I tahw hcum ytterp s’tahT“
,demrifnoc dna no dekcol saw noitagivaN .tnegru ton era evah I stnemucod eht dna ffo syad wef a denrae ev’I esuaceb yawyna ereh pots a gninnalp saw I“ .delworg tsomla eh ”,wonk I fi denmaD“ .tekcaj mrofinu sih fo lairetam ynihs railucep eht tsniaga gniltsur draeb dna enam yvaeh ,gniknilb
,worbeye lacizziuq a desiar aroL dna
van dna sretupmoc tseb eht evah sreiruoc taht od I sa llew sa wonk uoY“
,remmah eguh a ekil gnidnuop saw traeh siH
,denepo ti sa dekaeuqs hctah ehT
.scitenohp ni ”ainoliuqA“ tuo delleps eH
?uoY“ .delkcuhc kraM
”?kcehc ot lortnoc dnuorg deksa uoY“
,daed gnihtyna fo edih eht raew ot gnilliwnu
,lysaeW ,ytiniffAruF no
ylsuovren dewollaws retsamkcod ehT
.tuptuo on tub ,no gniog gnissecorp
eveirter ot ereht teg nac I fI
.thgir lla remraw saw tI
.htreb s’ainoeL eht dehcaer yeht sa derevihs eH
”?pihs ruoy htiw yats ot referp uoy dluow ro
,efildliw fo sotohp htiw pihc egami na dellif dah kraM dna
.moolg eht hguorht nwatfeT ta gnireep ,dias eh
nasuS“ .derewsna eh ”,ereh
”.ti no er’eW“ .dednopser eciov yrd s’regdab eht
.rodirroc ateb eht fo dne eht ta 3 etius evah uoY
,derewsna boR nehW
”,sseug I ,eurt s’taht ,lleW“
.devlover noitats eht sa
,ecnatsid eht fo htruof a derevoc dah yeht erofeB
.gnilims ,deddon noil ehT
,tuhs dehsoohw rood eht retfA
?huh rehtael laeR“
emit on detsaw arbez eht dna elosnoc sih ot ssecca kraM wolla ot edis eno ot ylteiuq deppils eH
.efink eht tuohtiw neve
.ylgnisiarppa ,ylnepo ezag s’kraM tem
egaggul fo elbmuj eht morf skcap owt rieht tuo gnitros nwatfeT dehctaw kraM
”.ti yub ot droffa t’ndluoc I
noitats eht otni llup ciffart eht gnihctaw dekil eh tub
”.em dedeen uoy fi ees retteb d’I thguoht dna rotacinummoc ym no segassem ycnegreme eht kcab deyalP
,esufer ot tuoba ,ezorf kraM
.gnireenigne rof edoc tigid owt eht dehcnup dna niaga rotacinummoc sih tuo dellup eh nehT
,no kcab sthgil eht teG“
.nwatfeT ot gnulc taht tnecs yksum gnisuora ylddo eht ta
.wonk ot detnaw aroL
.seod ti tahw ees dna
”,nees reve ev’I gniht tsedenmad eht s’tI“
.pacitnedi s’niatpac eht dna
.kram noitseuq emas ehT“
.oot revo taht dednah dna
.pmac gnikam erofeb potllih a ot pu dna
,nwonknu snosaer rof mih llik ot ylno ssenredliw eht otni ereh tuo mih thguorb evah tsum noil eht taht decnivnoC
”?taht eveihca noitats siht ro pihs ruoy no sretupmoc eht htiw gnirefretni seod woh“
.sretrauq s’werc eht dna aera tseug eht neewteb muisanmyg llams a s’ereht dna ,llah ssem ecivres-fles a evah eW
.ecaps ni ereh tuo kcuts syug owt tsuj er’ew ,denrecnoc m’I sa raf sA
,deppots dna derevihs eH
”,tuo seog ytivarg laicifitra eht fi yawa gnitaolf morf meht speek sihT“
.gniroolf eht hguorht detarbiv remmiks eht htiw tcatnoc citengam gnikam
.rednow oN“ .deksa eh ”?yllihC“
,mih dlot ehs ”,teid a no m’I“
.srekaeps eht otno boR tup dna langis eht degdelwonkca nasuS
,cinap ot tnaw mih edam noitcaer siH
.esle gnihtyna naht slamina dliw htiw gat resal gniyalp
.wap evissimsid a devaw noil ehT
.detroper regdab eht ”,mrow ro najort
”.tnemom eht ta deludehcs slavirra ro serutraped oN
”.ecirp fo sseldrager reffo taht tpecca ll’I ,deb dna htab reporp a evah smoor ruoy fI“ .dennirg eh
.eye eht ni thgir kraM gnikool
.tneserp eb ylbissop thgim hcihw sekans rof gnihctaw dna gnidael kraM
,ylediw dennirg aroL
”?erutaretil tneicna deiduts uoY
.gniwollaws retfa dias eh
.woleb tenalp eht morf
s’nwatfeT ”.demrofni su peek ,boR ,thgir llA“
.ti tuoba gnidaer morf tsuj ma I naht tenalp eht htiw railimaf erom era uoy nedlaV fo evitan
doots retsam eht
”,gnimoc emit R&R evah I“
,syaw dlo rieht otni kcab llaf ot ton snaidacsaC eht dnimer ot detnaw enoemos taht si sseug yM
.egaugnal eht ni tsael ta
.kcen sih fo kcab eht no dexif
.deknilb noil eht ”,taht wonk I“
,dias noil eht ”,ereh tiaW“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.smoor ruoy ot yek eht osla s’tI
.dnopser t’ndluow mleh eht
,taeb a gnissim tuohtiW ”.elcisynop
?eh t’ndid ,ti yas did feT ,haey hO
,ssarg llat hguorht delwarc yeht oS
ekil erom saw nedlaV no gnitnuh taht wenk eh hguoht neve
lenap mmoc eht no si reveohw ro ereh aroL hcaer ot nottub mocretni ruoy paT
.lliw I ,yletulosbA“
,raef rieht dellems kraM
”llaC fo troP esolC A“ saw sihT
,tnaruatser eht ot feT dniheb deliart kraM
.ylniatrecnu noil eht deye kraM
”,oot eraepsekahS s’ti kniht I“ .deddon feT ”.txetnoc
.eniw fo ssalg a dna
”.setunim wef a rof trof eht dloH“ .dias kraM
.ynobe dehsilop sa
.ecno deknilb yehT
,netfo os reggirt elfir eht gnisserp morf wap sih no retsilb a tog feT
.keehc s’kraM ekorts ot wap thgir sih htiw tuo dehcaer dna
.meht dlot regdab eht
,seiregrof era yeht fi wonk dna srepparw delaes eht ezingocer ot desoppus si retupmoc ehT
,elbat eht no nwod puc sih tes
latrop eht denepo feT
sllordeb tuo dial feT elihw
.gninraw fo maercs a evag neht
.gnihtyna deen ro snoitseuq evah uoy fi
.thgil mid eht ni ynnacnu erew seye gniwolg sih ,revewoH
,ssam dna thgieh lanoitpecxe fo enirdnaeL a
,sretrauq s’werc drawot ffo deirrucs dna ,deretnuoc ehs
.rotaderp a saw feT
.smetsys retupmoc ruoy no scitsongaid lluf nur ot gnireenigne rof sruoh 42 tsael ta ekat llits lliw ti tub ,secivres riaper etaidemmi rof uoy dekoob ev’I“ ,dedda dna
”,sseug I ,nietorp elbategeV“ .deksa eh
”,nwatfeT htiw etad ruoy yojnE“
,eb uoht tsdluoc tsaeb tahW“   orevO ovitlA yb
.ytlaiceps retupmoc a htiw reenigne feihc tnellecxe na evah ew ,ris ,seY“
,deedni llew yrev dessik eH
.edis nedlog a sah
.ylevarg egdab eht dna stnemucod eht detpecca feT
,yltpmorp eciffo sih ni eb dluow niatpac s’reiruoc eht taht gniwonK
”,ot elba eb dluohS“ ”...ti
,ti esufer ot detnaw kraM
dna sgniht gniraeh tuoba gnihtemos delbmum kraM
”,yltnerappa ,nwod rewop eht tuhs retupmoc niaM“
,neht dna won gnihctiwt rae na ylno ,kniht ot gniyrt
,esuap mih evag tsomla liat sih ta thgir noil eht fo thguoht ehT
ti fo htmraw teewsrettib eht gnihsiler ,aococ deppis eH
.noitamrofni eht degdelwonkca ylffurg boR dna
,sgnaf sih gniwohs ,dennirg eH
,taorht sih ta sgnaf esoht leef ot ekil eb dluow ti tahw gninigami flesmih thguac kraM
?uoy od ruf hcum taht evah t’nod uoY
”.tcaf ni ,ela naibeneD ekil fo troS“
.sulyts a nwatfeT dereffo eh
,noitats eht no ereh moor a ekat ot ekil d’uoy fi sretrauq tseug tnasaelp emos evah eW
.yvarg eht pu kaos ot daerb sih fo knuhc a elots dna
tuhs seye sih dezeeuqs kraM
resal sih htiw stniop dnasuoht a dedeecxe ydaerla dah nwatfeT nehw
reviuq dna eralf slirtson sih tel ot ton gniyrt
’airemmiC fo nanoC‘ syas tI
.ylsuoicipsus etutitsbus taem yarg eht deye dna
”?rewsna eht saw tahw oS“ ,deksa aroL
,draobyek lanimret eht no syek fo elpuoc a deppat eH
,orevO ovitlA ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
”?troser gnitnuh fo dnik emoS
”?aroL ,ssem eht rof gnidaeH“
waptoof detevlev a no deleviws dna ,derewsna feT
yvarg ni feeb derutluc deredro feT elihw
”?KO ,ti tuoba knihT
.dias eh ”,pu kcab emoc sgniht esac ni ereh ecalp ym ekaT“
,aera gninid sselwodniw eht morf stixe owt eht ta pu dekcilc gnithgil ycnegreme miD
.ria fo hsur detamotua sti htiw
.eeffoc emos flesmih tog feT dna
”?tsaeb a ot tcejbus ton erew taht
.deppart ylneddus gnileef
.deveiler er’uoy nehT
.pihs nwo sih ot hctah eht nepo ot
”.spo ni kcab niarb ym gnilttar saw tahw era SAC htiw trats taht seman eseht llA
trop gnikcod a drawot ylhtooms dedilg remmiks citcalag owt ssalc ehT
noissim tnerruc s’nwatfeT tuoba neercs eht no noitamrofni yhcteks ni gnillif
seye dekcab-tlig s’noil eht otni pu dekool eH
,meht ot wolg etinifed a dah seye s’niatpac noil ehT
.ti no rebmun a dna eman rieht htiw egdab leetsalp a hcae meht dednah ehS
woN‘ :si ti ereH .thgir llA“
”,gnitanicsaf era sepirts esohT“
.llew sa mih ot pu gnihctac saw noil eht tub
,tem tsrif dah yeht erehw moor eht ot pu dedeecorp dna rodirroc eht ot tuo tnew yehT
”?no gniog s’tahw ,boR“
”.esruoc fo seneg ym ni s’tI“
.yllautneve eno rehtona pu kcip ll’I“
.doof ytilauq pot esimorp t’ndid I .yrros m’I“
,dehctiwt kraM dna
…tuB“ .dereffo aroL
.rae s’arbez eht tsniaga thgir sreksihw sih gnignirb thgieh retaerg sih
.rehtona eno ot gnillac meht draeh dna
”,retsamkcod ,enod lleW“
”?boR ,tpmorp rehtona ereht sI“
.mih rof gnitiaw ,elbat a ta gnillol nwatfeT dnuof eh erehw ,moorssem eht drawot denrut eh
.drocer yrtsiger s’remmiks eht pu dellac ydaerla dah eh erehw lanimret eht ot noitnetta sih gninruter ,deddon kraM
.gnithgil ycnegreme mid eht ni niaga gniwolg erew seye
.ytivarg fo ssecxe eht fo etips ni doog tlef ti dna
”,railimaf sdnuos ti teY“
tnemucod detnirp eht tuo dleh eH
sotohp nezod a deppans dna ,snel otohpelet a dah kraM
.gnilims ,arbez eht ot redaer cinortcele erutainim a dednah eH
”,dab ton tub ywehC“
.mih detanicsaf ti tub ,hself detsaor eht gniruoved ylevitaicerppa noil eht hctaw ot ton deirt eH
.yromem fo tuo si ti revetahw ro mrow eht hsulf ot ti tratser dna retupmoc niam eht tlaH
.tenalp elbatibah ylno s’nedlaV fo eeg shtnet-enin eht rof kaew ylrevo ton saw eh os
,puc nwo sih nwod tup eH
.erehpsomta yvaeh eht fo taeh eht ro ytivarg eht rehtie yb derehtob t’nsaw noil eht ,ylsuoivbO
,doog dellems eh thguoht I“ ”.gnitseretni
.llah eht nwod ruof moor ni tik ruoy pu kcip nac uoY
.ainoeL eht no scitsongaid eht nigeb ot gniog saw tnatsissa sih taht troper ot ni dellac
.ecafrus eht ot nwod og ew nehw ti ssucsid ot ecnahc a teg ew epoh I
.kcab sulyts eht dednah eh sa
”?4 nedlaV tuoba wonk ot tnaw uoy did esle tahw oS
.lasufer ni wap a devaw ylno ohw nwatfeT ot kcab ti dereffo retsamkcod eht ,tekcop sih ni redaer eht gnidniF .haeY
.sruoh ruof ni troper lluf a meht evig ll’I
”?noitats ruoy no wap tes I ecnis reve em morf yawa gninnur neeb uoy evah yhw woN“
.hsiw uoy fi seitilicaf esoht fo esu ekam ot emoclew er’uoY
.niaga derevihs kraM dna dewohs sgnaf prahs sih taht os gnilims
.snoitcurtsni ruo rof yb gnidnats er’yehT“ .desivda nasuS
.dehguoc arbez ehT
.ereht retupmoc eht deireuq nrut ni ohw ,rotartsinimda dnuorg a ot hguorht gnireenigne dehctap ehS
.erofeb ti ekil eno nees dah eh taht dezilaer dna
.erutaretil tneicna ruoy wonk od yllaer uoY“
.niaga knil edistenalp eht pu gnirb ot snottub gnisserp nageb ohw ,nasuS ta dekool eH .mih dlot kraM
”.sedacsaC eht ni lavirra ym rof gnitiaw roolf eht gnicap si eno on dna evael fo syad wef a ot deltitne m’I
raey a tuoba rof dnuorg dilos no fooh tes t’ndah eH
.nietorp ruoy htiw siht yrT“
,dna mih ydaets ot sredluohs sih fo hcae no wap a tup noil eht dna
.etiteppa sih fo etips ni mirt yats ot hguone evitca dna gnuoy osla yletanutrof tub ,yrgnuh syawla saw eH
.tcaxe eb ot ,drawoH .E treboR“
.esnopser tnatsid eht emac
.meht woleb edistenalp dna
.eciffo siht evael uoy sa tfel ruoy ot s’tahT
”,kraM ,driew tsuj s’tahT“
.nwatfeT ot denrut eH
.esac yna ni ytiroirp pot steg llac ycnegreme na esruoc fo dnA“ .dias kraM
.emit siht ylduol ,niaga dehgual nexiv ehT
”.ti ekat I ,evitan a er’uoY
reward a morf niahc kcen a htiw egdab leetsalp a dellup eH
”,aedi ’nikcirf on evah I“ .deksa eh
”.pu su kcip ot elttuhs a dnes nac yeht os ,etaucave ot dnetni ew fi eciton s’ruoh na tnaw yehT
,tib a denethgirb feT
fo dnik emos s’ti skniht ereh ffeJ
”.yltcerid enatleB ot gniklat neeb ev’yeht dna wonk gnireenigne tel I .mih
.ainoeL draob no redloc neve eb lliw tI“
.wap yrruf gib a yb derevoc yletaidemmi saw tI
,tfihs ruoy ffo teg uoy nehw tuB“
.retnirp eht fo tuo dils noitazirohtua riaper a dna ,syek deppat eH
nac uoy os sixa tnednepedni na sah myg eht tub ,eeg flah eno ot tes si ytivarg noitatS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,orevO ovitlA yb
.redaer ynit eht no desucof dna tcnitsni taht deniatnoc eh ,lliw fo ecrof htiW
.ereh rehto hcae htiw lamrof taht t’nera uoy erus m’I“ .ylteiuq dias eh
.eno fo deeps dna selcsum lufrewop eht dah
.demmid dna derekcilf sthgil eht ecnis dessap dah ruoh na tsomlA
.ti detekcop dna ecived sih desolc kraM ”.detsop em peeK“
”.yrassecen semoceb ti fi wonk meht tel ll’ew tub ,tey suoires taht t’nsi ti meht lleT“ .deddon kraM
.drawrof deunitnoc
,daeh sih koohs enirdnaeL ehT
.elims elttil a htiw mih ot deddon ehs dna ,ojoR aroL
.knil mmoc eht revo dekaorc eciov s’regdab eht
.krad eht ni neeb dah ti ecnatsid eht fo htnet a ylno demees moor ssem eht ot rodirroc dethgil won eht nwod kcab gniklaW .dias aroL
.erofeb ti nees reven ev’I ,thgir er’uoY
.noitats eht fo saera elbissecca ylcilbup lla otni uoy tel lliw egdab sihT“
dna deraelc si ycnegreme eht meht llet dna lortnoc dnuorg llaC .sruo ton
mih ta worbeye na desiar ylno feT
.depeeb lenap mmoc eht erofeb dessap dah ruoh rehtonA
.edisa yart nwo sih gnihsup ,deddon kraM
.evreserp emag a yleritne tsomla si tnenitnoc nrehtuos eht tub ,esruoc fo ,ereht neeb reven ev’I“
.rednow I won tub
,ytisoiruc dna ygrene fo lluf
.puc eht dnuora sdnah sih gnipparw dna
a sa dna noitacude laitnatsbus a evah uoy retsamkcod a sa wonk I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daeR   .orevO ovitlA rednu nozamA ro sdaerdooG ta dna
.edistenalp noitcartta tsiruot elttil a s’ereht dnatsrednu I“
,ylthgil kcen s’arbez eht deppin feT
,ytilanoitar lla nwod gnituohs dna gnigar stcnitsni sih htiw
.edam hserf ,ffuts hserF“
”?ew era tuo gnipmaC“
.depmuj dna deltrats arbez eht
.knalpgnag eht nwod mih dewollof dna ,skcar drawrof eht ni
.ecaf a gnikam ,egareveb toh eht htiw nwod ti dehsaw dna
skcor eht gnoma ni degnulp kraM
,sselnopaew yldrah saw feT
.dniheb morf gninetaerht gnihtemos dna
.spil reh desrup nasuS
,snoitacinummoc enituor deldnah aroL elihw srehcuov ograc dezylana dna stroper delif kraM
”,doog gnikool sa llew sa
.rotacinummoc eht otni deyarb ylraen
”,ecudorp lacoL“ .deralced eh
”.smetsys ruoy revo kool nac eh sa noos sa sriaper eht tuoba uoy htiw hcuot ni eb lliw reenigne feihc ruO
”.seneg ym ni s’ti ,yas uoy sa ,lleW
.neercs reh morf daer tsuj dah ehs tahw morf ydaerla ti wonk t’ndid ehs fi sa
,rethgual htiw delworg
”?netfo neppah siht seoD“
”,lortnoc dnuorg yreuq ll’ew ,no dloH“
derewsna kraM ”,t’nseod tI“
”,sruoh thgie tsael tA“
”,neht og s’tel ,KO“
”.ydal ,smaerd teewS .ageV rof gnidaeh deeps LTF ta ffo sekat noitats siht yad eht si teid ot deen uoy yad ehT
”,erutaretil htraE dlO“
feT ot rotacinummoc a dednah dna snottub dehcnup nexiv krad ehT
.ylthgils gniddon erofeb mrofinu s’nwatfeT fo hsas citamolpid etihw eht revo nur seye sih tel hprom arbez ehT
.edistuo eht htiw stnemeerga edart lla dekcolb dna ,tsinoitalosi na saw eH“ .dias eh
,tenalp eht no ylimaf dna
.yawyna gnidnats no detsisni enam sih fo esab eht ta sriah fo ffur ehT .mih raef ot ton
,dalas dessot pu gniyek
,elbat rieht ot txen llaw eht ni lenap a nepo dils dna dehgual kraM
.potelbat eht no dnah sih dial dna
”.peels emos deen I dna“
.gniwollaws erofeb elihw a rof dewehc dna etib yhtlaeh a koot eH
”?revetahw ro esnecil ro noitavreser a teg ot tluciffid ti sI“
.liart sih gnidir rotaderp suorovinrac a
”,lotipaC eht ni noil ehT“ .deddon feT
,derepsihw noil eht ”,erehT“
.ti dnuof eh tub ,rotacinummoc sih ot teg ot tekcaj rehtael eht rednu gid ot dah eH
daeh sih desiar noillats a nehw dreh gnitcepsusnu eht ot esolc yrev erew yeht dna ,edis eno ot tib a devom dah
.eritta s’kraM ta elzzum detniop reh nwod gnirats
,stigid eht dexelf dna wap a tuo dleh eH
kcen sih fo kcab eht no sgnaf esoht tlef eh dna
.niaga mih gniwollof erofeb hguorht pets ot arbez eht rof detiaw dna
ecnaraelc pot htiw reiruoc a
”.tuo dnif nac uoy tahw eeS
,trop noitadilav s’lanimret eht otni ti dils dna eluspac eht detpecca kraM
”.ni thgir em gnittel rof tsilaiceps noitacinummoc ruoy ot sknahT
s’nedlaV .siht ekil ciffart tnatropmi teg netfo t’ndid 4 nedlaV .oot tekcaj mrofinu sih denethgiarts eH
.denworf ehs dna
,edutitta ytsan a dna
,aococ toh detceles kraM
.gnikniht ,rae eno dehctiwt dna deknilb eH
.ezag s’arbez eht deciton feT
.yas ot drah saw edisni morf yllautca ro thgil detcelfer morf tsuj rehtehw
,nwatfeT niatpaC sa ylsuoiruc dehctaw retsamkcod ehT
.spam fo tekcap a tuo dellup dna spacitnedi rieht dekcehc krelc noitavreser ehT
noil ehT .derevihs dna
.gnirewsna erofeb hteet sih revo eugnot sih fo pit eht nar noil eht sa kcen s’retsamkcod eht nwod nar llirht ddo na dna ,tcaf ni
elosnoc lanimret reh dniheb dekcud ehS
.referp uoy fi flah a dna eno sa hcum sa ot ti esaercni
.retsiger rewol eht ni eciov sih peek ot gniyrt ,derekcin eh
seye gniwolg s’feT gnileef osla tub ,noitats eht htiw railimaf tsom saw eh ecnis yaw eht gnidael kraM
”.ytiruces ro rewop on htiw wols tsuj ,suoregnad ton s’tI
mih rof edisa dils latrop eht dna
.gnireenigne pu dehcnup eh ,gnirevihs llitS
,dellortnoc dna tnetepmoc syawla saw nexiv ehT
”.peels emos teg su fo tser eht elihw ereh hctaw eht ekat lliw aroL
doohlaof s’kraM tuoba snoitseuq fo maerts tnatsnoc a pu gnipeek feT
.ti ta deffins noil eht
”,3 enecS ,1 tcA ,raseaC suiluJ“
”.erots dna pihs ot tluciffid dna evisnepxe si hself nworg-erutluC
”.ereht teg nac ew tub ,sedirrevo launam fo elpuoc a ekat lliw tI“
,noonretfa taht etaL
.mih nevig dah    eht deyaler kraM
.flesmih niatpac eht naht rehto werc on dna
”.kraM ,ainoeL eht htiw nwatfeT niatpaC s’tahT“ gniyas
”.esnepxe taerg oN
.depib a rof yltfiws dna
,anuaf eht tuoba kraM ziuq ot deunitnoc eH
.dias arbez eht ”,ffo ti daeR“
,egral ton saw noitats
.tcaf ni yrtsudni gniwerb eht rof niarg ruo stropmi beneD
deraeppa ti tsal ta tub ,noziroh eht dnuora emac moor snoitarepo eht litnu
.gnitalusni dna tfos gnihtemos htiw denil dna
”,ereh retsamkcod ,enitraP kraM“
dnoces a rof delbbow eH
”.yllanigiro ereht saw tahw rednow I
tuo dellac kraM yllanif dna ,etunim a rof detiaw yehT
”,ris ,ycnegreme eht fo lortnoc edistenalp deifiton ev’I“
”.era ereht smetsys
.noitats eht otni teg ot smargorp pukcab eht desu dna ereh ni dellac I
,dewehc dna etib evitatnet a koot eH
.stekcap atad citamolpid eht no slaes detpyrcne eht detadilav yllarutan yeht ,retupmoc s’ainoeL eht ot knil rieht edam werc s’boR nehW“ .reh
,esruoc fo ti detcepxe eH
,desolc seye sih htiw gnittis llits saw kraM
.ylffurg derewsna boR
.erom on wenk eh yas ot dah kraM litnu ,4 nedlaV fo yrotsih eht dna ,erutluc eht
,ovitlA rednu onimA yrruF ro
.tamolpid a dna nameltneg a saw niatpac reiruoc ehT
”.sretrauq thgit era esehT“ .feT delbmur
.dnuos yldneirfnu ton dna mraw a ,dehgual eh nehT
.yrt ot tahw mih dlot kraM
.eno siht tuoba gnihtemos saw ereht tuB“
.sdiuqil toh eht gnippis ,rehto hcae gnicaf tas yehT
,erom dna ruoh na rof no deggard gniklats eht sa dna
.ti ot deneppah gnihtemos tuB .boR ,wonk I ,seY“
”.ereht wodniw a s’ereht tsael tA
”.nwod ti nip ot gniyrt era dna
sevooh ruof htiw
.lla ta ylesolc taht gniwollof ton
,ereht tuo dloc denmad saw tI“
.tnaruatser eht ssim t’nod dna ,hO“
,dreh eht dna flesmih neewteb ecnatsid eht gnisolc saw hprom arbez ehT .dewollof dna
,mih dniheb teef xis tuoba gnidnats niatpac eht was eh ,dnuora gninruT
,decnalab ylluferac si ygoloce ehT .tserof dna sdnalssarg htob
.nwatfeT ot kcab ti gnissap
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.detnaw eh tahw dnif ot smret hcraes eht gniretne ytluciffid dah dna dloc eht morf gnirevihs saw eH .mih dlot kraM
.evreserp eht fo esoprup niam eht si loop eneg eht gnivreserp dna
yltfos dehgual noil ehT
”,emag nuf a saw tahT“ .wap sih htiw
”?gnitnuh og ot tnaw uoY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.latrop eht tuo dap ot
.nwod saw metsys noitagivan
.won erutluc ni taht worg ew tub
,dreh regral eht wollof mih ekam dluow msaisuhtne s’hprom noil eht taht gnipoh
.nwod ylbamuserp sretupmoc reh htiw erehwyna gniog eb t’ndluow ainoeL
kcod eht fo knulc llud ehT
tnemom eht rof ainoeL dekoohnu ev’eW“
”.yleritne rood taht rof hctal eht dessim I“ .dias eh ”,huD“
.desirprus kool ot nrut s’feT saw tI
spihs luah gnol neewteb liam detfihs-relppod gnissap
,elimiscaf elbanosaer a ro hself tae ot deen yeht ,eruS
.htuom eht no lluf mih ssik ot ylno
.elfir resal sih fo egnar fo tuo tsuj saw
,retnuoc eht ot tnew dna deddon eH
.delworg eh ”,dnatsrednu I ,hO“
”,ti dnif t’ndluoc yehT .seY“
”,oga sraey 02 tuoba litnu metsyS sedacsaC eht revo rotatcid enirdnaeL eht saw V suiluJ“ .deddon feT ”.raseaC fo noitanissassa eht gnittolp era yeht erehw enecs eht s’tI“ .meht dlot eh
?syad wef a rof em htiw edistenalp gniog redisnoc uoy dluoW
.ekilssenisub dna raelc yltcefrep sselehtenon saw taht rrup teiuq a ni dias eh
”.taht nialpxe nac eh os boR ot enil a nwatfeT niatpaC eviG“
,llits yal arbez eht
,mih ot dias feT
.suolucidir saw taht ,oN
’.lotipaC eht ni noil eht htod sa sraor dna ,sevarg snepo ,snethgil ,srednuht taht
.emankcin taht yb kraM gnillac ot nekat gnivah ,dias eh
.yletaidemmi nasuS dias
”,elosnoc eht no egassem citpyrc rehtona tog ev’I“ ”?boR“
,deretne yeht sa yltnatcepxe pu dekool snexiv htoB
.aroL ot deddon kraM .delworg feT
.snoitarepo ot pu og s’teL
,yltneg mih dnuora smra evissam depparw dna
,htooms dna tfos saw eugnot s’noil ehT
tub suoitatnetsO
,ssenkrad raen eht ni mih dniheb doots nwatfeT
.kraM ,netsiL“ .detatiseh eH
,reffo taht tnaem yllaer I
nwatfeT taht gnisirprus saw ti os ,tuo gir retupmoc tsetal eht lla dah sproc citamolpid yllausU
duolc yreve taht dna
ecuas ycips a detceles dna
.ssensuoicsnoc sih otni niarbdnih sih morf pu tperc dna
”,nasuS ,ti no m’I“ .tnelis tnew
moor eht otni ylksirb deppets
.ecnatsid eht ni slamina yranigami ta gnithgis ,elfir resal sih htiw deyalp dna
.mih dniheb tuhs edils rood eht tel dna
,neercs ynit eht etanimulli ot yek eht dehcuot retsamkcod ehT
.loot erucinam elttil a tsuj s’tI“
.txetnoc tahw dna yalp hcihw ,si noitseuq ehT
gnieb tneitnes yreve ni doog si ereht taht seveileb ylnrobbuts ohw esroh a si ohw
,ecivres citamolpid eht ni saw pihs ehT
.mih dniheb tsuj ecneserp s’noil eht fo suoicsnoc yletuca llits saw kraM ,sselehtenoN
.yltnedive ,revihs eht deciton nwatfeT
.eerf kaerb ,elggurts
,seciffo eht hcaer ot niatpac s’ainoeL eht rof setunim ylno koot tI
.flesmih fo etips ni dehgual arbez ehT
.deksa eh ”?siht ,hO“
.deneppah gnihton tub ,mih otni gnab ot feT gnitcepxe
.7 edacsaC no smetsys eht ot derrefsnart erew stekcap eht litnu deneppah evah t’ndluow taht yllamroN
.selzzum rieht erofeb ria eht gnitsim
.reerac ecaps a esoohc ot emac eh woh dna
dnalssarg eht otni sretemolik net tuoba dekih yeht dna
”.ereht nwod ediug deniart a erih ylisae nac uoy“ ,dias eh ”,feT“
.nruter ot nageb sraef eht taht
?yeht t’ndid ,krad eht ni ees dluoc stac taht demialc sgniyas dlo eht ,lleW
.yad lla taht od ot detnaw ev’I“ .yltfos dias eh
.ti fo tuo nekat hcton llams a ylno htiw taem citehtnys fo yttap a dleh llits taht etalp a edisa devohs dah feT
.retupmoc s’ainoeL eht rof esarhpssap eht s’tahT“
,knilb desirprus a htiW
.dnuof saw etouq eht rof knil oN
.mocretni eciov eht revo mih ees t’ndluoc reenigne eht hguoht neve ,deddon kraM
dnah dereffo s’kraM detpecca niatpac noil eht sa neve
.derepsihw noil eht
.rodirroc eht ni delttar dna gniknilb kraM gnivael
.stnemidnoc dna sgnisserd fo selttob ezeeuqs gnilaever
.ytisoiruc dlim htiw dehctaw feT
”.tsael ta dnasuoht 05 mih tsoc ylbaborp gniraew saw eh tekcaj mrofinu tahT .rehtael saw tI“
.ti dereffo dna daerb eht fo knuhc egral a ffo ekorb eH
.tnasaelpnu taht t’nsaw ti ,yaw emos ni tey dna daed
delims nwatfeT tub ,locotorp ot noitnetta dna
.llew ytivarg eht fo tuo reets ot emit dah llits I dna tuo deppord margorp van eht neht tub
.sredluohs reworran s’arbez eht dnuora ti decalp dna tekcaj rehtael sih deppiznu eH .deunitnoc feT
,noitpo aremac eht nesohc dah flesmih kraM
,dias eh ”,arbez ,xaleR“
,dedaol segdirtrac eht dna ,citnehtua dekool hcuop ehT
”?ycnegreme eht fo enatleB eht deifiton uoy evaH“
.raf os devirra dah owt ylno dna
tropsnart dnuorg eht ot sngis dewollof yehT
,noitats eht fo nrevac eht edisni deppart tlef eh ,gniniart recaps tseilrae sih ecnis emit tsrif eht roF
,snoitarepo drawot kcab detrats yehT
”,retsamkcod ,ereht ysaE“
”,wonk ot ton nagev a tsurT“
,meht retfa gninnur saw eh ,tnatsni na nI
.delims eh ”,sey ,yllautcA“
,reenigne feihc eht ,egnahc hctaw erofeb setunim 03 tuobA
.pollag a ta nialp yssarg eht ssorca ffo koot dna
.esnopser a rof gnitiaw fi sa kram noitseuq a htiw
,tuo kcab ti tips dna pacitnedi eht fo ecnatpecca deknilb lanimret ehT
”?neht gnipmac dna gnitnuh emit ruo koob ew od woH
,dap erutangis a revo ti gnicalP
.kcod ni spihs owt ylno erew erehT
niaga dnuorg eht no erew sevooh sih ecno ylkciuq derevocer eh ,llitS
t’ndluoc I“ .deretne aroL dna ylwols denepo latrop eht nehw
snoitar deird ezeerf morf laem a deraperp kraM
”,retsamkcod ,snoitacinummoc ta
,ydob s’noil eht fo taeh eht htiw mraw saw ti tub
a otni nezorf eb retsamkcod ruoy gnittel fo em esucca ot uoy tnaw t’ndid I dna
*** ”.tiaw t’nac I“ .feT dias ”,dooG“
”,neht tae ot gnihtemos rof ssem eht ot og yllausu dna
”,sraw eneg eht erofeb dna levart ecaps erofeb ,arreT ot kcab yaw eht lla seog ti ,hsilgnE lanigiro eht s’taht fI“ ”?ti si dlo woH
deen ew fi reenigne sih fo secivres eht dereetnulov surdnA niatpaC“
.ylkaew delims retsamkcod gnuoy ehT ”.ees I ,KO“
.tekcaj s’nwatfeT fo lairetam rehtael eht llems dluoc eH
,ylraluger myg eht ni tuo krow ot deriuqer erew werc noitats lla ,yletanutroF
”?naem taht seod lleh ni tahW