.niaga tey tuo yrc tibbar eht edam taht revuenam a
,rehtie dniheb raf oot t'nsaw soreA
',wolg uoy nehw lufituaeb er'uoY"
,emoc d'eh erofeb emit fo rettam a eb ylno dluow tI
,hcamots sih ssorca derettalps
.ssalc eht morf elggig evitcelloc a gnirehtag
.depsag nosduH '!doG ,hO"
.cissalc sselemit a
?mih yaper ton eh dluoc woh
.noisufnoc gningief ,daeh sih detlit tteuqroT rosseforP
,tolipotua no saw ydob sih fi sA
,yltneg os reve ti no gnisrun
elkcuhc a htiw kcen sih debbur nosduH
?tegraT rosseforP
keew eht rof krowemoh eht tuo dellac
taorht s'nosduH morf emac lworg gnilbmur peed A
,nosduH fo tnorf ni debmilc eh
.barK .rM taht fo erom oN
gniruoP .resserd eht morf ebul fo elttob eht debbarg dna
eniuneg erew sdrow siH
,nageb nosduH ,wonk uoY
,eeffoc rof yad yrevE
.nwo sih ni sdnah sih koot dna
,edisni kcab kcid sih demmals eh
.ezag s'rehto eht gniyduts
,sdaeh rewohs owt htiw rewohs egral a saw tI
hU .deksa tteuqroT rosseforP
yawa detlem sserts sih llA
,saw gnihtyreve taen woh ta desirprus elttil a saw eh
.emoh teg tsuj uoY
ecnelis rettu ni tneps saw edir rac ehT
.dias tteuqroT rosseforP
,ylduol denaorg nosduH
,leengarD lorrE yb tcA ssalC A
,deticxe sa tsuj saw
.gnol yad lla yug siht yb deldduc gnieb dnim t'ndluow eh
mra sih no dnah a ecalp ot riah redlo eht rof ylno tellaw sih rof tnew dirbyh gnuoy eht
.erofeb lufrednow siht tlef dah gnihtoN
.regit eht htiw did eh tahw naht repeed gnihtemos
,erusaelp fo ecaf a otni detrotnoc serutaef deggur sih yaw eht
?regnol elttil a tsuJ
.ecaf eht ni mih gnittih ylraen
.ti morf gnippird
,deviecer tsuj d'eh msagro gniwolb-dnim eht dna rennid retfA
?lorrE ,taht saw tahW
.wollef redlo ffurg a morf
'.nuf eht yojne dna
?derednow eh ,egakcap elohw eht ro sllab sih tsuj ti sI
hcuot eltneg a hcuS
.hctorc sih derevoc ti os kcapkcab sih gnitsujda
.nuf evah dna kcils yatS
.soopmahs dna sgnihsaw-ydob fo tnemtrossa na htiw
.mih edisni soreA tuohtiw neve
,yadot ereh daer uoy tahw ekil uoy fI
?raeh uoy ,slauqe yawrood sih dniheB
,erofeb morf egassam redluohs eht ot ralimis
H" .ruf tfos sih hguorht gninnur
.nosduH em llac esaelp dna
.ytirailimaf fo mlaer eht otni
.ebul hcum oot sa gniht hcus on ,rebmemeR
,naom yreve ,hctiwt yreve
,txen sneppah tahw ees ll'ew neht dna
.yas dluow ynneL sa ,reven ro won
enohp sih ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut lorrE
,edisa stbuod dlo gniworhT
,ssalc fo dne eht rof dellot lleb eht ecnO
,tsehc s'dirbyh eht egassam ot
.enif m'I ,ris ,yrroS
,ylleb sih ni selcric eltneg ,wols debbur eH
dehprom ylwols psarg tahT
.desuora erom leef tub pleh t'ndluoc soreA
,knird sih nwod gnittes
.depsar nosduH '!esaelp ,oddiK"
,ecaf s'lorrE fo edis eht desserac dnah A
.keehc gniwolg sih tsniaga bmuht sih gnihsurb
.dias lorrE '!wow ,hO !hO"
,htaenrednu hself elppus tub mrif taht ,ylleb evisnapxe
',haG" .lluh yreppils
.tsomla ynneL fo mih dednimer tI
.mih no nwod deyarps retaw toh eht sa
,siht did yeht sA
revo dehcaer dnah eerf s'ynneL
.mih ediseb thgir gnidnal
.rebmem s'nam gnuoy eht ta gnilevram
pots ot erehw fo eguag a sa snaom s'rosseforp sih gnisu
.elkcuhc ytraeh a tuo tel nosduH .hgU .moT ,naem I
.noitceffa sih htiw llits
.taht hctac t'ndid I ,yrroS
.yellehS ,yug siht fo tol a tegroF
trihs sih fo snottub wef tsal eht didnu nosduH
,deb eht no tas dna mih dnuora deppets nosduH
.gab eht fo stnetnoc eht htiw desirprus saw dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
tcA ssalC A saw sihT '.noh
,elam redlo eht dias ,revo thgir eb ll'I dna sserdda ruoy em txeT
,ecrof hcum tuohtiw dna
,ynneL ,sknahT .oddik ,kcul dooG
dnim sih gniworht saw etad tsrif sih fo aedi ehT
.slirtson sih gnilkcit esnes tnegnup eht fo ffihw lluf a teg ot
'.nonnac a ekil er'uoy ,dik ,suseJ"
.cilbup ni erew yeht ecnis yllaicepse
,dnim ni tnediser eht htiw tub
.derettum soreA '!haeY"
.mih deppots riah redlo eht nehw rood eht tuo yawflah saw lorrE
.emoctuo elbirroh tsael eht ylbaborp saw sihT
dehcnelcnu dna dehcnelc ti sa ti fo tuo gninnur detrats yletaidemmi tsomla muc siH
,erucidep a flesym teg ot tops elttil a wonk I
.ecaf ruoy no kool eht nees
.elbaroda thgir nwoD ?etuC
gnitirw sih tuoba suoires erom teg ot gniyrt si ohw
nosduH sdrawot dekool eH
?ssalc ot kcoj a sraew ohw eno ehT .peY
.mih retfa pu debmilc eh sa
,wolg skeehc sih htiW
,ikaK yb uoy rof daer
?netfo ereh emoc ,hO
?og tel ot em tnaw uoY
,yawa dnah sih dellup eh sa
ylthgit steehs eht deppirg eH
yrroS .sdnah sih ni eton eht ta gnirats ,snaej krad dna
,dees fo noitceje hcae htiw debborht kcid s'lorrE sa tib a denethgit pirg siH
?yrgna mih edam eh daH .gnidnammoc erom
,dnah s'nosduH htiw flesmih fo edam d'eh ssem eht derimda dna
.drac sih pu dloh dna
.ruf nworb ytsur dna
,noos ereh eb dluohs dooF .pu knird woN
,redluohs sih no tser dnah a tlef lorrE -- I ,niaga ,naem I
.riah s'lorrE hguorht debmoc yltneg dna
smra sih desiar ylsuoituac dna ylwols eh sa flesmih dedlocs yllatnem lorrE
'.nosduH ,pu taht
.htaerb peed a werd lorrE
,dnah sih pu dleh tteuqroT rosseforP
.deen htiw gnibborht flesmih tlef lorrE
.mih tuoba gnirulla os erew taht seye sih saw tI
.emoh teews emoh ,era ew ereH
rehtruf mih dehsup etatsorp sih no tluassa deunitnoc eht sa
,mih ta dekniw eloh knip thgirb s'nosduH
dnah s'lorrE koot dna
.tnaruatser eht ni mraw etiuq gnieb ydaerla ti etipsed revo lla toh tlef eH
,mih fo tnorf ni thgir gnidnats saw
.eman tsrif sih yb rehcaet sih gnillac fo thguoht eht ta
.detnaw uoy tahw tog uoY ?trops ,ecaf gnol a htiw s'tahw oS !yobattA
.tnatropmi repus gnihton ,thgir lla s'tI
,etammoor sih dnif ot rood eht denepo eH
edaf t'ndid elims s'rosseforp ehT "?yadrutaS siht
elzzun ot nageb tibbar redlo eht nehw repmihw a tuo tel ygrokS ehT
.ezirp sih fo weiv a teg ot
.elkcuhc derit a tuo tel soreA
.ti hctac etiuq t'ndid I
,ezag s'riah dlo eht rednU
.hsulb ot nrut s'nosduH saw woN
.ecaf s'nosduH ssorca daerps krims suoived a sa
.tnemom feirb a rof yawa dekool nosduH sa
spets eht pu delbmarcs htoB .sriatspU
.tsrubtuo neddus eht ta depley soreA .dekrab nosduH
.eloh s'nosduH htiw pu flesmih denil dna
.kcab devaw ylyhs lorrE dna
,sredluohs sih otno gnidloh ,saw eh erehT
.retnuoc eht dniheb morf pu dekrep saw llaw tuots a sa delttar
.dnim sih ni lewot a dah ydaerla eh ,emoh devirra lorrE ecnO
si yrots s'yadot dnA
.tsehc ruf yarg sih ffo gniwohs
tlef taht sgniht esoht fo eno tsuj saw tI
.llew tnew ti ekil sdnuos tahT
rood eht ta gab sih deppord lorrE
.gnihgual nwod ekorb eh erofeb
.yug eht htiw devil eh dna
.muc sih htiw noisseforp sih llif ot detrats eh sa
.yticapac yna ni devom soreA revenehw dehtaerb eh yaw yredduhs eht neve lla
noisiv sih ni srats was llits eH
.tfahs sih fo niev yreve gnola decart eugnot s'lorrE sa delruc seot siH .kcus yreve
erp fo tnuoma enecsbo tsomla eht fo eton gnikat
.eloh s'nosduH fo tuo flesmih desae ylwols soreA
ylthgils rrup dirbyh gnuoy eht gnikam ,eugnot sih otno deloord muc-erp fo bolg A
,roolf eht dehcuot teef s'nosduH sa nevE
redluohs sih revo decnalg soreA
.elppin sih gnihcnip rehto eht dna
.ti fo seztirps wef a flesmih gnivig erofeb rood moorhtab eht ta dekool lorrE
riah ydob reppep dna tlas fo taoc taht
,did ti sseug I ,haeY
.sllab dna kcid sih tsniaga gnidnirg detrats toof eht nehw pley a kcab tib lorrE
.derepsihw nosduH ',xaler tsuJ"
.toh ytterp saw ti sseug I"
.eninac regnuoy eht ot derutseg eh dna
,detacorpicer erew sgnileef eht
,nemodba s'nam eht ot sdnah sih derewol lorrE
.ydob sih nwod dedacsac retaw eht sa
,ynroh fo erutxim elbirroh a
'.lorrE ,deretsulf er'uoy nehw etuc os er'uoY"
elahni ot gnirutseg
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,taeb a gnissim tuohtiW
hsub s'tibbar eht ni ecaf sih deirub eH
,erom ecno teef sih ot gnitteg detrats soreA
.gniht nmad eht dniheb morf gniwolg mih ees dluoc yeht wenk eh tub ,unem eht dniheb gnidih hcum ytterp saw lorrE .os epoh I
.egelloc eht raen tops elttil taht ot og nac ew ,tnaw uoy fI
,redluohs s'nosduH tsniaga kcab denael lorrE
.norom a ekil dekool tsuj eh
',ti ekil uoy ,flesruoy ekil yrf llams a rof dnA"
ot detnaw I .esle enoyna ksa t'ndluoc I" .yltfos delkcuhc nosduH '?erus uoy erA ?eM" .tseuqer eht ta ediw tnew seye 'soreA
sregnif s'nosduH
norpa deniats ,desaerg a ni desserD
dnah rehto sih htiW
eidooh eht gniraew
ev'dluohs uoY
.gnineve siht eerf erew uoy fi ees ot gnillac saw I
redluohs sih dnuora nworht mra na tlef yletaidemmi tsomla dna rac eht fo tuo debmilc lorrE
.erusaelp rieht fo htob ot hcum
.etad sih ot sserdda tnes
.leengarD lorrE yb
.denruter tnaruatser eht morf krims suoived taht dna
ssa s'nosduH sa pil sih no nwod tib soreA
.meht nihtiw noissap eht dna ,erac eht
,pu thgil tsuj d'yeht ,gnihtemos tuoba deticxe saw eh nehw semitemoS
seye eulb enillatsyrc esoht otni gnikooL
,oga sraey owt rehtom sih morf yawa devom tsrif lorrE nehw tem d'yehT
.ecaf s'nosduH ssorca daerps nirg gib A .dias yellehS
.edistuo daeh sih dekeep ynneL
.yawevird eht ni pu llup rac a gniraeh
,htuom sih otni meht fo eno koot eH
.nruter on fo tniop eht ,ti saw sihT
,moor eht fo tuo dehsur yldeirruh eH
'.steehs eseht pu naelc dna rewohs a barg ,no emoC
tsehc sih nihtiw morf tnemtnetnoc fo elbmur peed a draeh eH
.erusaelp s'nosduH ot hcum yawa evag elcsum yrebbur ,thgit tahT
.kcoc sih fo ecnesba eht ot eud
,esirprus sih ot hcum dna
.resolc ni lorrE dellup eh sa
.tcepxe ot hcterts a fo hcum t'nsaw eh
.esnopser a rof detiaw dna enohp sih otni rebmun eht delaid lorrE
?gniog yeht erew erehW
.tsul dna ewa fo kool a htiw gnihctaw
,erab osrot sih gnivael ,ffo ti deggurhs dna
?raew ot gniog eh saw tahW
,sregnif sih no kcus ot detrats dna
.hgual ot nrut s'nosduH saw ti woN
gninoitseuq morf mih deppots nosduH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
ssa s'nosduH nemes fo tsalb hcae htiw
naorg a htiw skeehc sih derevoc eH
.ffo mih dekcus eh sa rethgit riah s'dirbyh eht gnippirg
.riah ybbuhc eht dnuora parw ot
'.od uoy nehw seye ruoy ni rednow hcus evah uoy tub
.sniol sih ta gnileef esnetni na saw ereht ,os hcum oS
.sresuort s'nosduH ni eglub tnenimorp eht elgo tub pleh t'ndluoc tsuj eh ,stroffe sih etipseD
.doog oot tlef tsuj mih edisni eigroks ybbuhc eht gnileef tsuj
.tsrif rennid a em yub dluoc uoy ,taht ekil em gnillabeye peek ot gniog er'uoy fI
,spih s'nosduH dnuora smra sih depparw eH .dewollaws eh sa
,teef sih ot tog lorrE sA
nosduH ffo dellor soreA
.teerts eht ssorca krap eht drawot
.tnaw uoy fi nac I
.edis eht ot ffo moorhtab a dna
',noisacco eht rof desserd emac uoy smees
,mih morf yltsom ,ria eht ni noisnet lauxes saw erehT
ezeerb lanmutua na leef dluoc lorrE
spih sih gnipsarg yltneg
.derats eh yaw eht htiw suoivbo repus ylno saw tI .lufrednoW
.rosseforP yeltroP eht otno gnikcol seye nworb sih
.yawa gnillup erofeb sdnoces wef a rof taht ekil dleh yehT
,sfeirb sih ni debborht rebmem sih sa gnitnap saw eH
.delworg eh ',ti kcuS"
ot si unem gninid rieht dna
.taebtraeh s'riah eht fo dnuos eht no ni denoh eh sa
.rac eht fo ecnelis eht hguorht tuc eciov s'nosduH sa depmuj lorrE
.niaga ecno neerg detanimulli erew sworra dna
niks sih gnola erif lacirohpatem fo htap a tfel nosduH morf hcuot hcaE
,kcoc s'lorrE fo edisrednu eht gnola regnif sih gniggard yltneg tub
.kcul doog gnirb teef s'tibbar taht htym a neeb syawla s'ereht
?yadrutaS siht etad a no tuo uoy ekat I nac ,mu ,uoy era ,hu ,I
.stnetnoc sti gniwonk yllaitrap etipsed
,yawa dedaf dah oga stnemom ylno morf raef ehT
?yas ot desoppus eh saw tahW
.gniht a raeh t'ndid I ,yrrow oN
taem gnibborht s'nosduH fo ssenpmad mraw eht fo eciton koot lorrE
.kcid s'nosduH ot spil sih gnitcennoc avilas fo gnirts a htiw kcab dellup lorrE '?oddik ,he ,ti kcuF"
naom dna psag ot nageb nosduH
eht ot gnivom eb ot gniog er'ew kniht t'nod I
ecaf s'riah eht ssorca ekorb elims eguh a ylnedduS
,drawrof tohs muc fo tej tsrif eht sa spih sih dekcub nam gnuoy eht
.nwo sih naht retrohs
.dnuorg eht ot derewol seye s'lorrE
wohemos tub ,ollej ekil tlef seenk sih
,daeh s'lorrE fo pot no dnah sih decalp yltneg nosduH
.elggij lufyalp a ylleb sih evag nosduH '.haeY"
.mmh-mM .deremmats lorrE ?os taht sI
.ti tuoba yrrow t'noD
-- tnereffid saw sihT
,dirbyh eht morf noitcaer yreve gniretsiger
.keehc sih tsniaga dehsurb ti sa pmuj kcoc kciht eht tlef eH
'.detnaw uoy sa gib sa t'nsi ti fi yrroS"
,elam redlo eht dnuora smra sih depparw dna
,ssa sih daerps eh ,htaerb rof gnipsag yllacitcarP
.emithcnul rof yadsruhT rehto yreve
,ti deppirg dna kcoc sih drawot nwod derednaw dnah siH
.tuo uoy pleh lliw ereh ynneL elcnU .daeh yzzuf elttil ruoy yrrow uoy t'noD
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
?tih a teg enoemos did ,hO
.lorrE dna nosduH fo edis eht ta pu dekrep eh
,tsehc sih ta ti demia dna
regnif sih werdhtiw ylwols eH
.ylralimis desserd
diulf etihw ybbew eht eroda ot pu ti gnidloh
.tnacirbul fo elttob a ot depat eton a dnuof eh ,ti gninepo nopU
pal s'nosduH ffo dils eh '!hO"
'.doog yllaer leef em gnikam er'uoY" .dekrab lorrE '!on
,kcil a ti evag dna esolc ni denael eikroks ehT
esuap thgils a saw erehT '.laiceps yrev
,uoy truh annog t'nia I
.eros repus tsuj era enim
.selppin nwo sih fo eno kaewt ot pu dehcaer nosduH
?rennid a ekil cissalc erehwemos gniog eb yeht dluow erehW .erehwyreve
,erusaelp ni deddil-flah seye s'tibbar eht htiW
'?em kcuf uoy lliW"
,drawrof hsup ot deunitnoc eH
.seitfif ylrae sih ni nameltneg redlo ylriaf a saw eH
hguone tsuj esolc ni denael eh
.stun evitisnes sih revo dehsaw eugnot hguor
,kcoc gnibborht sih morf wolf ot detrats ssip toh fo cra nA
,tsenoh eb nac I fI"
.tniat s'tibbar eht degassam yltneg soreA nehw os erom neve
,htaerb peed a gnikaT .OX OX
?etad tsrif eht no xes evah ot gniog yeht ereW
,detrons nosduH !ynneL
.tib a xaler ,dik ,zeeG
.mih fo tnorf ni sdnah sih gnidlof
elbat rieht ot pu dellorts ,retnuoc eht morf tar ybbuhc eht ,yellehS
.mih ot siht did syawla krims dna kniw lufyalp tahT
.ssa erab sih no ria nepo gnivah fo gnileef ddo na saw ereht tuB
.elum sih ni htgnel eht gniflugne ylluf
.hguoht ,ti did eH
.mih retfa gniliart soreA htiw moorhtab eht otni yaw sih delbmuts eh
.saera etamitni tsom sih derolpxe eugnot tsiom taht sa xaler ylneddus dna
.ylleb egral s'nosduH no
,ti dekil fo dnik I
,pil sih no nwod gnitiB
.eglub s'eninac regnuoy eht fo eniltuo eht decart
'.soreA ,esaelp ,em kcuF"
leef em gnikam fo yaw a dah syawla ev'uoY"
.retsim ,rennid ot tuo uoy gnikat eno eht saw I ,dekcehc I tsaL
.tfeh artxe eht gnildarc
.noh ,ti ot desu teg ll'uoY
.eno tsal eht fo lufepoh elttil a mih edam gnittes nus eht ta gnikooL
elkcuhc fo tuo del riah regral ehT
spil sih ot dnah delios a thguorb eH
.tibbar eht fo tuo eniru fo strups erom gnixaoc yllufesoprup tsomla
,gnikorts ylluf ton
.rac eht ot ffo gnirepmacs erofeb ,dias lorrE
llaw eht tsniaga gninael nosduH ees ot
.erp gniloord
,ymmalc repus erew sdnah siH
.mih ffo sehtolc sih deleep eh sa elims taht gninigami tsuj
.esac ni tsuj gab etad a uoy kcap d'I derugiF
.elbat eht fo edis s'renwo sti ot kcab taerter toof eht tlef eH
,luftsul saw seye sih ni kool eht dna
,ylmraw delims nosduH
,rehto hcae ta derats yehT
setunim wef tsrif eht roF
ecnelis no tas yehT
.ffo ti gnippot maerc deppihw dna maerc eci fo dnuom a htiw sessalg egral owt htiw
dnah s'nosduH nehT
,kciht eht hguorht dekorts dnah gnilbmert sih sa don a eganam ylerab dluoc lorrE ?taht ekiL
,smodnoc ,slewot dnah fo elpuoc A
.riah tsehc fo tlep yriw
peek tsuJ" .flesmih ekorts ot detrats eh sa
nwod dekool eh sa
.ezeeuqs gnirussaer a ti gnivig
mih htaeneb ssip fo elddup gnilooc eht fo eton koot nosduH
.wonk I ,shtnom xis rof ssalc ym ni neeb ev'uoY
.raewrednu sih hguorht gnikael dna htrof gnilbbird emoc eerht
.etad a flesmih thguorb ydduS
.rehtie emit elohw siht stnap sih ni gnibborht saw kcid sih taht pleh t'ndid tI
.tnemeticxe sih niatnoc ylerab dluoc soreA
.esruoc niam eht su teg 'nignuoy eht tel ll'I dna ,yllihP ,staolf reeb toor owt teg em tel
ylleb sih ssorca gnihsalps
.worb sih gnilggaw ,dias nosduH
',ris ,oot od uoY" .detnap nosduH
,krow ot tnew yeht oS
.spih sih dekcub dna
.tnemom kaerb-ro-ekam sih ,ti saw sihT
'.em tel ,ereH" .thgir
... os demees tibbar redlo eht esuaceb egnarts os saw ti tub
.yarps ydob detnecs-tnim a dna ,ebul derovalf
,ecnartne s'tibbar tuots eht tsniaga kcid sih desserp ylkciuq eh thguoht hcum tuohtiW
'?huh ,ees uoy tahw ekil uoY"
,sgel sih gnola gnibburd seot htiW
.elkcuhc a tuo tel nosduH
trohs gnihton saw nosduH
pu sgel s'nosduH gnihsup yltneg
,soreA ,laiceps era uoY" '.nosduH ,laiceps
,ecaf 'soreA deppuc yltneg dna
.ruf sih hguorht nwod nur diuqil wolley eht gnihctaw
ecarbme tfos a ni
,nosduH edisni llits saw kcoc sih fo daeh eht os tsuj kcab gnilluP
.spih sih fo pop yreve htiw
,siht yb desirpruS
,tahw uoy lleT .llac ot gniog t'nerew uoy thguoht tsomla I .deedni ma I
.ecaf sih ssorca daerps elims a sa dnah sih tsniaga denael soreA .dias eh
kcas ytfeh sih morf gnitaname ksum tnegnup ehT
.eglub s'lorrE ta nwod dehcaer eH
.ylleb sih otni kcab sih gnisserp
,loohcs ,efil emoH
.did eh sa gnilkcuhc tibbar redlo eht gniraeh
.ot dah tsuj I .yrros os m'I .zeeg ,hA
.mih ta gninnirg hcuoc rehtael eht fo kcab eht revo gninael ynneL ees ot pu dekool dna
.tnemtraped htam eht fo daeh eht saw tteuqroT rosseforP
,tibbar eht ta gnikooL .depsag soreA
.thguoht eh ,ynneL ylnO
,netfo os yreve hcnul rof ereht ni pots I
.taes regnessap eht otni delttes eh sa gel s'yob eht gnittap
nosduH dna flesmih ees dluoc eH
tfahs eht detaoc dah taht bmoc-
denigami d'eh naht rekciht saw tI
?uoy lliw ,rehtegot ti peek ot yrt tsuJ
,pu nehserf em teL
.detcartsid os erew uoy yhw ees I won ,hA
?yddub ,yadot dnim ruoy no s'tahW
.elkcuhc a draeh eh erofeb esuap feirb a saw erehT
',mmh-mM" '?pup ,taht ekil uoY"
-- fi pots nac ew soC ?suovreN" '?haeY"
.oga keew a ynneL htiw thguob d'eh eno yllacificeps
.keehc sih gnikorts yltneg bmuht sih
.uoy ot pu ti ekam nac I yllufepoH
.nosduH fo pot no debmilc soreA nehw neve ,rehtona eno morf ekorb reven seye rieht
seot s'nosduH fo enO
,oot uoy evol I--I"
.noinapmoc edicignuf lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikaK m'I
,edisni mih tel nosduH nehW
?kcab mih ekil tteuqroT rosseforP diD
.txen deneppah tahw morf flesmih pots t'ndluoc nosduH ".ereht
.tnemssarrabme ni niaga euh neerg erutangis rieht no koot skeehc siH
,ecalp eht hguorht gniklaw
.tuo gnikael-erp fo tnuoma reehs eht ta delevram tsuj dna pit eht dnuora regnif sih delriws eH .dias eh ',wow ,hO"
,denottubnu trihs-sserd sih
,teiuq yltsom saw laem ehT
.ecnecsenimuloib s'rehtaf sih teg ot dah eh ,esruoc fO
.flesmih lorrE naht retrohs owt ro daeh a ebyam saw
kcen s'lorrE gnilkcit draeb yffurcs sih
'?he ,noitcartta niam eht si siht taht eidrib a morf draeH"
,snoitcurtsni sih gniwolloF .elahxe neht dna
.eno naht syaw erom ni
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioVehT ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
tteuqroT rosseforP
deb eht fo retnec eht drawot detoocs ylsseldrow nosduH dna
wodniw eht tuo gnikool dna
.ylitraeh hgual yellehS dna nosduH htob draeh eh nehw denethgirb skeehc siH
,afos eht no tas nam gnuoy ehT
,gnibbur eltneg a otni
hgis derit a tuo dehtaerb tub
stsev retaews dna
.flesmih rehtag ot lorrE rof tnemom a koot tI
.seye erab s'lorrE tsniaga sbur eglub sih sa
.thguoht lorrE ,detsuB
.egde eht ot rehtruf dna
?rosseforP ,haey ,hU
.egakcap yksum s'nam redlo eht fo ffihw peed rehtona gnikat ,deddon lorrE
.eninac retrohs eht morf hgis suoredduhs a gnixaoc
,thgit s'nosduH fo edisni repeed teg ot pu sgel sih dehsup soreA ".lufituaeb fo
.kcid sih fo ecnuob eht neve
?eivom a ekil relooc gnihtemos ebyaM
.rehtruf yna
.tnemssarrabme ni pu eidooh sih htiw ssalc eht fo tser eht tneps lorrE
.noisufnoc ni deknilb lorrE '?eM"
.ni thgir edils daeh ytaem s'tibbar ybbuhc eht tel ot htuom sih denepo yletamitlu tub
,nehctik eht morf tuo gnikeep ynneL was eh eye sih fo renroc eht revO
.ecnelis ni derewohs owt eht
.kcid sih ot yltcerid tohs yticirtcele fo tloj a ekil tlef ti sa
,hcuot sih htiw thgil detrats eH
kcid sih gnikorts dnah eno htiw tsul no ylelos gninnur saw eh
,elcihev eht edisni morf evaw elttil a evag nosduH
,hgiht sih tsniaga gniniarts skcoc sih saw ti thguoht tsuj eh tsrif tA
nikserof eht yb derevocnu doots ti sa desopxe yawflah saw daeh ehT
.sdnah sih ni koob a dna no swen eht htiw
,pal sih ta nwod dekool lorrE
,ecnahc sih saw sihT .mih ta gnimaeb
,emit eht fo tsoM
,mraw 'soreA nehw pley a niatnoc ylerab dluoc eH
.rewsna t'ndid lorrE
,ediw tnew seye s'lorrE
spmubesoog gnimrof niks sih
.detrexe eh htmraw eht saw os
!tuo-tuc draobdrac uoy ,kcab mih guH
,nehctik eht ot kcab yaw sih edam regit regral eht sA
.seye sih fo kcarc eht neewteb ni degdew
?raew ot gniog eh saw tahw woN
.neerg thgil fo tnit a no koot ecaf s'lorrE
ecaf sih no elims a htiw kcoc gniyarps-llits eht debbarg soreA
.noituloser raeY weN sih fo trap sa
.pu taeh skeehc sih tlef dna
.hcuoc eht no mih ediseb ti tes dna kcapkcab sih pu dleh ynneL .dias lorrE
.ti evol ll'uoy ,no emoC
.lorrE ,ereht remaerdyad a erew syawla uoY .delkcuhc nosduH
.dias nosduH ,rof eid
tfahs eht dnuora delruc sregnif siH
riah sih elffur dnah gib a tlef eH
.detacorpicer nosduH dna
.emoh gnikool-yzoc rehtar a fo tnorf eht otni rac sih dellup nosduH
.ti pleh t'ndluoc eH
,til ylthgirb ylniatrec saw ti tub ,tuo krad saw tI
?lorrE ,ykcul gnileef uoY
,gnitnap tfel erew htoB
,seye eulb deddil-flah esohT
.drawer sih saw nam redlo eht morf naom ylbmur peed eht dna
,selppin sih gnihcnip detrats eH
.msagro esnetni na ffo gnittes suht
der thgirb a erew skeehc s'nosduH
.ylleb s'eigrokS gnuoy eht debbur dna
.yawa gniretlews dna
,etatsorp sih tsniaga dnirg kcoc 'soreA tlef eh sa depley nosduH
eno siht piks nac uoy
ylduol dehgis dna
.gniziteppa gnihtemos dnif ot deirt dna unem eht pu dekcip ylkciuq eH ...mu ,I ,hO ?lorrE ,rof yrgnuh uoy era tahW .kcip sih s'tI
,em ta kool uoy yaw eht nees ev'I .uoy ,haeY"
,kcid sih gnirehtals s'taht dnah sih otni tnuoma larebil a
,repeek a ylniatreC .ydduS ,elbaroda s'eH
,hcuoc eht otni tsrif-ecaf denael eh sa
.no-drah lluf a otni denrut imes sih sa dewollaws lorrE
.bur hcae neewteb sessik detnalp dna
.yrros m'I .dias nosduH
,spat wef a htiw ,dna
,ynneL yb neve ton
ksed sih sdrawot kcab denrut eh sa
.taht ekil ti gniyarps tuoba yrroS"
tuo deirc eigroks ehT
.ylthgils nikserof sih morf tuo gnikeep daeh eht htiw ,kciht ytterP
-- I" .muc sih fo stnanmer yna tuo gniklim yltneg
,pil sih no nwod gnitiB
.rosseforP ,uoy knahT .deddon lorrE
'?od ot tnaw uoy od tahW
,deunitnoc nosduH
.ti htiw tcatnoc edam ria gnineve dloc eht sa
.snaej sih hguorht rebmem sih gnidaenk toof a saw ti dezilaer ylwols tub
,lorrE drawot sedirts wef a koot nosduH
.setalp rennid sa ediw tnew seye s'lorrE
,yseehc dnuos yam tI
sfeirb etihw sih tsuj ni mih gnivael
,dirbyh eht rof yllausnes elttil a denaom eh erus gnikam
',worromot ylreporp klaw t'nac I taht drah os em kcuf ot uoy tnaw I"
,dnim lliw pup eht kniht t'nod I .nosduH lausu ruoy trats tsuj ll'I kniht I
ti nwod gninnur dna
.citsalp detanimal desruC
ffo sehtolc sih deppirts lorrE
.riah kcalb yssem sih hguorht gnikorts
.keehc eht no kcep a ygrokS eht evag nosduH
,ffo lorrE ekorts ot nageb eh dna
?yddub ,ereht yako uoY
don ot deganam lorrE
.elbaroda gnirats sih gnillac
,yrutnec eht fo tnemetatsrednu eht saw suovren saw eh yas oT
,no rewohs eht nrut ot derebmemer ylerab nosduH
.elkcuhc a tuo tel tteuqroT rosseforP
kcab tis tsuj uoY .thgir llA"
.ynneL ,thginot esab driht
.tuo mih deksa eH
'.uoy hcuot ot detnaw syawla ev'I ,lleW"
,lorrE delcricne smra egral sih dna ,yawa deppord
skcals ni desserd pu dewohs yllausu taht riah nworb tuots A
.kcen sih no elbbin dna
knird sih gnippis ylippah saw ohw erah dlo gnilims eht ot unem eht revo morf pu dekcip lorrE
,nosduH saw ereht dna
.esac ni tsuj ,dias I sA
.elbaraebnu erom hcum os gnileef eht edam ylno taht
.sllab fo tes egral a saw htaeneb gnilgnad dna
.tnemssarrabme dna ,emahs
?no hsurc a evah uoy eno ehT .huh-hU ?riah ehT
.tpecca ot mih tcepxe t'ndid tsuj I .wonk t'nod I
.hcrop sih morf yks noonretfa eht ta gnikool
.don ot deganam lorrE
siht sI .ih ,mU .olleH
tuo uoy ekat I naC
,lleW" .skcos kcalb dna
.won thgir gnihsulb saw eh tnuoma eht morf
.flesmih esopmoc dluoc rosseforp eht os
.derumrum lorrE ,huh-
'.taerg s'tahT .stnuoc ti erehw llams t'nia uoy ,lleW"
-- t'ndid I .yrros os m'I
,pac llab yttar a dna
.yrteop fo evol sih
?tnemom a rof uoy ot kaeps I nac ,lorrE
yllufyalp gnilworg
,no kcoj eht tup dna
,engardoreA yb
'.ti pleh t'ndluoc I
yltnerruc mih dah llits taht elbat eht rednu tnuts taht htiw yllaicepse
desseug evah dluow reven eH
.repap fo eceip a tuo dellup dna
nam gnuoy eht ot kniw a evag eH
detlem noitatiseh sih ylwolS
.oB ,spitregnif ruoy ta m'I"
.dnah dna ylleb sih ssorca gnirettalps
.mih dekcor yltneg rosseforp eht sa tuhs tfird seye sih tel lorrE
,ni denael nam ehT
'.neppah ti tel tsuj ,hhS" '?duh-h-
,stnemom wef a rof ereht doots eH
tnemom feirb a rof dekool eH
,gab sih ni tup dah ynneL tahw ees ot emit siht koot
.ecnelis eht kaerb dluow eh tlef
.pirg mraw sti htiw kcoc sih no nwod derab
,suovren lla m'I woN
.ecnetnes-dim mih gnippots
.kcen sih debbur ylsuovren lorrE
.eh si sihT .deksa lorrE
,gnol os rof retfa degnol d'eh
.kcoc sih no nwod depmalc
.sllab sih drawot nwod htgnel kciht eht gnola sessik eltneg gnitnalp ,wols detrats eH
,dehsinif saw laem eht nehw tuB
.derettum lorrE ,gib os saw eH
?redro ot ydaer uoY .rof deksa uoy staolf reeb toor owt esoht s'ereH
'.oorakcub ,fo demahsa eb ot gnihtoN"
'-- uoy erus uoy erA .thgit er'uoY"
dapeton sih no gnihtemos nwod gnilbbircs ,dias yellehS
.ecalp ym ot daeh dna rennid barg nac ew ,noh
.hcamots sih ni derettulf seilfrettub sa ecnelis ni pil sih tib lorrE
.mih ta dekniw tteuqroT rosseforP
.shtuom rieht ni doof deffuts yeht sa drow a gnikaeps ytrap rehtien
.gnos a morf enut a demmuh eh sa gniyaws yltneg
gnihcuot ylerab erew seson rieht os
.ssip dna ,muc ,xes fo tnecs eht htiw dellif moor eht htiw
terces ni gnol os rof retfa denip eh nam ehT
.denaom lorrE ',uoy knahT"
,ruf dekaos sih hguorht sdnah sih nar eH
,guh eht morf yawa dellup ylwols tteuqroT rosseforP .og uoy erehT
.erom ecno deddon dna dewollaws lorrE
.sregnif kcils sih htiw rood kcab sih gniddorp yltneg
?gnirats ym yb derehtob ton er'uoy oS
,pal sih otni mih gnillup dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
morf eson eht no kcep kciuq a tub ,pil sih no delbbin loreA '.uoy eb
sevlehs erew meht htaeneB .owt rof tcefrep
lorrE .moorhtab eht otni gnikcud erofeb keehc eht no kcep kciuq a dirbyh eht gnivig ,dias nosduH
.htgnel eht gnola erusaelp fo stloj elttil gnidnes pmup hcae
.tif guns eht gnirimda
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY  .emit txen
.sredluohs sih depsarg yltneg sdnah fo riap A
dehctih gnihtaerb siH
.pu kcip enil rehto eht no enoemos draeh eh nehw taeb a deppiks traeh siH
,tar tuots eht fo edis eht otni woble sih debbaj dna dennirg eH
,soreA did rehtien dna
.laed a gib taht t'nia tI .noh ,xaler tsuJ
nwo sih tsniaga tser ot emac dnah egral A '.uoy evol I"
dnah egral sih dah nosduH sa
.sey gniyas uoy etaicerppa I ,wonk uoY
.sgniht tuoba deklat yeht sa sdnah gnidloh
.draob eht esare ot gninrut erofeb
.yadrutaS siht tuo uoy ekat lliw I
tnemom a rof gnitnuts ereht doots ygrokS ehT
.taerG .dias lorrE
,soreA htiw gnola tuo deirc nosduH
'.ezigolopa attog t'nod uoy os
derednaw dnim sih sa
,ylthgils detatiseh lorrE
',doog os leef uoy ,doG ,hO"
.yrrufoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy
,pu dekrep srae sih ,riahc a fo kaerc eht gniraeH
.deddon nam redlo ehT
.emos kcab denael dna
,rewol tnew dna htab-eugnot sih desuap loreA
,pu dekrep srae siH
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,ria eht hguorht gnittuc eman sih ta pu depmuj ygrokS gnuoy ehT !lorrE
.tuo ti tel ylteiuq dna htaerb peed a werd eh
.dirbyh erom's eht ot eloh knip thgirb sih ffo gniwohs
.kaeps ot os ,naidraug a sa gniw sih rednu yob eht nekat ecnis dah eh dna
.kcoc sih hguorht kcohs neddus a gnidnes
.ees ot ynneL rof pu ti dleh dna tekcop sih otni dehcaer lorrE .yad gnoL
.ssalc retfa tuoba deklat ew ekil ,wonk uoY
.kcab sih debbur yltneg dnah a sa
.mih fo tnorf ni seenk sih otno dna
.erolpxe ot lorrE rof lla
mih fo trap a tub
,nepo rood moorhtab eht draeh eh
.elbatrofmoc gnihtemos raew ot erus ekam ,hO
.edisni del saw eh sa
,no-drah gnigar a dah llits eh dna
'.did I sseug I ,haeY"
.tsehc desopxe ,yzzuf sih no ti decalp dna
.tnaruatser dezis-yletaredom a ot pu dellup nosduH
.tuH rosseforP ,gniht eruS
.yab ta sthguoht dwel erom sih peek ot gnilggurts
dnuora emac dnah rehto siH
.taert ym eb ll'ti tub
.flesruoy yojne dna kcab kcik tsuj ot ecalp ecin a s'tI
,gnihtolc fo eceip eht derimda eh sA
.delkcuhc tteuqroT forP
.dirbyh eht ta nwod dekool eh sa
.pu uoy kcip ot yb gniws ll'I dna em txet tsuJ
.plug elbidua na tuo tel eigrokS ehT ?lorrE ,uoy tahT
.deniatniam dna ecin srepmuht dlo eht peek
.thgiled s'nosduH ot hcum
.detnap nosduH '!tihs gnikcuf yloH"
,dirbyh rellams eht oT
.dias lorrE ,suovren elttil a llits m'I
?pihsnoitaler laer a fo gninnigeb eht siht saW
pu dehcaer tibbar ehT
.emoh og ot detnaw tsuj eH .rettam taht rof derac lorrE ekil
.kcab daorb sih tsniaga gnitser
?hcaeb eht no klaw a ekil yseehc gnihtemos neve rO
.pu sbmuht a dna
.tniop siht ta mih gnisaet saw nosduH wenk eh
dloh s'nosduH morf dellup yltneg lorrE
.ecarbme eltneg a otni nam gnuoy eht dellup rosseforp ehT
,rehcaet a sa tsuj ton
,nwod dna pu nam gnuoy eht dekool
.derettum lorrE ,taerg sdnuoS
,detcepxenu guh eht saw ylno toN
,tnesba erew stnap siH
,moor sih ni erew yeht fI
neffits nosduH gnileef
.woleb steehs eht otno
.etulas lacimoc a evag yllihP
.repap fo pils lluf a mih dednah dna lorrE ot kcab denrut eH
,parts kcoj elprup a saw hsulb ot mih tog tahW
,rE .niaga ecno denethgirb skeehc s'lorrE sa
moor s'nosduH otni dna
,eltsihw flow a tuo gnittel
.semitemos ti eveileb ot ekil I
.peerc a saw eh thguoht nam eht woN
kcil hcae htiw deluam dna deredduhs tibbar ehT
.ediw tnew seye s'ynneL .s'tteuqroT rosseforP tI .ynneL ta pu gnikool saw eh os revo dellor lorrE .ylduorp dias ynneL ,dirbyh ykcul uoY
.did uoy fi ti etaicerppa d'I
.taerG .deplug lorrE
uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
,gnirutcel fo yad gnol a retfA
ton s'ti ,haB ?kcolc eht ta gnirats neeb eh dah gnol woH .kcit ,kcit ,kciT
daeh sih dniheb sdnah sih dekcolretni nosduH
'?huh ,siht rof deticxe eb tsum uoY"
.ylerar yrev nees d'eh eno tsal ehT
.ereht yaw elohw eht hgiht s'lorrE no gnitser
mih drawot deppets ylteiuq eH
srae sih ni depmuht traeh s'lorrE
tteuqroT rosseforP
.egakcap sih fo thgis eht ta delevram dna raewrednu sih evomer tibbar eht depleh eH
,sllab sih rednu ti dehctih dna goj eht nwod dellup nosduH
.pots nac I ,ti htiw elbatrofmocnu er'uoy fI
,egral s'nosduH leef ot
.srae sih ta ylgnihtoos os gnar dna
.tnaruatser eht fo kcab eht sdrawot htoob a ta nwod tas lorrE dna nosduH .niatpaC ,eya-eyA
.ysatsce yb dellepsid gnieb niap yna
,etuc adnik s'ti kniht I
,kcab dnirg ot ton dah eh gnihtyreve koot tI
.enilefil a erew ti fi sa tsehc sih ot kcab sih gnihctulc
,suoiciv erom emaceb stsurht siH
drawpu derednaw sdnah siH
,rosseforP ,hcum yrev taht ekil d'I
,nam redlo eht dniheb delffuhs lorrE
.pu dessem tib a si romuh fo esnes yM .yrroS
erif no erew skeehc sih erus saw lorrE .noos uoy eeS
.deremmats lorrE "-- t'ndid I
.gnileef elat yriaf taht ti gnivig
.pu dnah rehto sih thguorb eh
.ereht thgir ,ereht thgir ,soreA ,kcuf ,hO"
,erac t'ndid eh tuB
.sgel sih neewteb eglub eht no dednal yeht sa gnilkcuhc
.hcuot hcae htiw detnurg dna denaom nosduH .neve yrgnuh
.niaga mraw gnitteg detrats yeht sa
.uoy eltrats ot
pirg sih dexaler tibbar redlo ehT
dnatsthgin eht no elttob eht tes eH
,repeed saw eciov siH .nosduH .rM
.gnineve yadrutaS saw ti litnu pu etad sih rof ydaer dna demoorg saw lorrE erus gnikam
.ezah a otni eikroks eht evord
.tnemtnioppasid s'lorrE ot hcum
afos eht no gnittis regit yltrop a ,ynneL
poohw a tuo tel ynneL .eno eht s'tahT
deb dezis-neeuq a htiw deppiuqe
,elcsum fo gnir esnet taht dessap ylisae daeh eht
dees etihw yklim fo snobbiR
.hctorc sih tsniaga sserp gnihtemos tlef eh nehw sthguoht sih fo tuo dellup ylneddus saw eH .ecin eb d'tahT
.eson sih no ssik a detnalp dna nwod denael ynneL .dias lorrE
,erofeb siht ekil dehcuot neeb reven d'eH .yltfos gninaom
lleb daehrevo na fo elgnij tfos eht sA
.niaga kcoc sih drawot devom dna
.tnecs sih fo ffihw peed a koot eh sa
.nosduH .5 1 0 7 3 2 9 8 6 4
.mra sih debbur ylsuovren lorrE .delkcuhc nosduH
,regnuh eht ees dluoc eh
nosduH litnu evird eht fo stnemom wef tsrif eht rof
tcA ssalC A yojne esaelP
,seirf dna regrub elpmis a fo setalp owt htiw denruter eH