,rehtorb gib sih sa remmiws a doog sa neeb evah ton thgim eH
.hctam eht fo elddim eht evael ot dah yeht eveileb t'ndluoc reldA
,kcab sih no sdnah s'ak'naS tlef eh sa sthguoht htiw decar dnim siH
,slamina fo tuo retaw kcus ekil ssorg gnihtemos od dluow skarakS yhw deksa eh nehW
dehctaw ylluferac saw ynoloc eht fo tuo dna ni levarT
,llah eht nwod gniohce spetstoof tew rieht htiW
.retaw fo tib a htiw dellif
,edis etisoppo reh ot pu emoc ot egaruoc eht pu werd yerroT
,rof ereht saw ynoloc eht tahw saw tI
.daeh sih revo ecalkcen a tup dah taht edis eht saw os tuB
,ytic eht ni srehto ekil
,rehtorb elttil sih tem evah ot yppah saw ak'naS wenk reldA
.retteb leef ot detrats yob eht
.yrgnuh saw yerroT esuaceb ,doog saw hcihw ,txen emac hcnuL
,enog erew snoigiler dlo eht elihW
,nihcru na dekcip eh
,deraef snailitper eht tahw saw siht tub ,yawa raf os
.ti ekil ot denrael eh tub ,mra artxe na ekil daeh sih fo kcab eht gnidloh eson taht gnileef ot desu gnitteg emos koot tI
,nihcru hcum oot netae dah nailitper gnuoy eht mih dlot ehs sa noos sA
.kcul elpoep rieht gnirb ot ynoloc rieht dliub ot detnaw dah skarakS eht—did reven sredael nailitper eht siht morf gnihtemos denrael reldA
,demahsa dna desufnoc
.skaerb yduts gnirud dna sessalc retfa pu gniteem
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mih dnuora mra reh stup ehs dnA
,yxalag eht fo edis rehto eht morf emoc dah egatoof ehT
,skarakS eht fo lufraef llits stnerap dna sdneirf sih htiw tub
,edis reh ot emac reldA sa
.setirovaf s'reldA fo eno
,ak'naS gnittespu rof ytliug gnileef llits saw yerroT
.ecaps siht edisni sneila ynam os
,thgil eulb ni dehtab saw moor ehT
,ebut eht fo dne rehto eht ta degreme eh nehW
.od snailitper ekil tsuj
.dnuor gniwollof eht rof skcits sih fo eno pu evig ot gnivah
,ytic eht ssorca gnimmiws skarakS dleh sdaeh rieht evoba sepip tnaiG
.stfig eerf gnitteg rehtorb elttil sih ees ot taerg saw ti dnA
.rehto hcae htiw tcatnoc ekam ot gniyrt ,meht gnigniws
.ynoloc eht dessorc-ssirc taht sebut retaw eht tuo yrt ot detnaw dah yerroT   .3     .deerga ehs dna
,ak'naS ot dezigolopa eH .degnirc reldA
.hsuh ot lla gniksa erew moor eht fi sa
,retaw tsuj lla s'ti flesmih ot gnikniht reldA etipsed dnA
.tnereffid saw ebut siht tuB
,nwot fo tsaE tresed eht ni sisao gnimaelg eht tuoba wenk eh elihW
.rebmahc eht gniretne ecnis drow a nekops t'ndah reldA dna ak'naS
yad eno emoh ak'naS wollof ot elba saw reldA os
,taes sih fo tuo depmuj eh ,emag eht otni os tog eH .dereehc reldA
,noisufnoc htiw dehctaw yerroT
dessik skarakS taht denrael tsrif eh nehw mih no feiler eguh a saw tI
!skcits rellams otni trapa ekorb
.deveileb ylluf t'ndah tub
.hsid gnikool ssa dab eht morf retsgnuoy eht edaussid ot drah saw ti ,devirra ti ecno ,llitS
pets tsrif a gnieb ti tuoba dednuoba sromur dna
,mih ot tuo dehcaer repeekpohs tsrif eht nehw deracs saw yerroT
.dnuor wen a langis ot taeb murd txen eht rof
,roolf mraw eht no teef sih tup dna retaw eht fo tuo debmilc eh sA
.ydob sih ffo erusserp eht peek ot demees edam saw ebut eht woh tuoba gnihtemos tub
did yeht sa elbmessasid dna elbmessa ylsseltroffe os skcits eht gnikam ni devlovni saw ygolonhcet gnizama tahw derednow evah dluow yerroT
,yerroT ot sliated eht fo emos nialpxe depleh ak'naS
.kcen reh dnuora dleh ehs retaw fo tib eht dehcuot neht
.ti detterger ylkciuq eh
rehtorb sih fo daeha decar dna flesmih lortnoc t'ndluoc yerroT
.ti ta derats ak'naS
,tnew eh nwod rehtruf eht mih ezeeuqs thgim erusserp retaw eht gnikniht
,skarakS eht lla yb dehsinotsa
.nevigrof saw lla ebyam thguoht eh dna
ytiniffAruF no dnuof eb nac cimoc ehT .kceramaS
.retteb tlef tahT
,tnemom a rof dehctaw eH
.ecneirepxe gnizama na saw ti dnA
detnuoc yllanif yerroT sa ,hcae seceip xis—
.esora elbuort fi etalosi ot ysae dna
,doofaes rehto dna hsif gnilles stnorferots fo sderdnuh
.anera eht ot tnew yeht ,sdrawretfA
taht gnihctam msaisuhtne sih
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,erauqs ytic eht ni ak'naS tem yehT
eman eht rednu ytiniffAruF no dnuof eb nac krow esohw tsitra D3 a
.retaw eht hguorht snihplod ekil gnidilg
;nees dah eh gnihtyreve rof lufknaht os saw eH
.selitper orhtna delbmeser taht sdog depihsrow ecno dah srotsecna karakS taht ak'naS morf denrael dah eH
,tsrif ta yerroT deirrow tI
,daehrevo gnirewot gniliec eht
.ti erahs ot tiaw t'ndluoc reldA dnA
,daeh sih gnisserac eson reh
,seceip eht dehcatta dna ekorb yeht woh ni diulf os srethgif eht ,tsaf os deneppah ti fo llA
,sregnomraw sa noitatuper a dah skarakS eht ,meht morf dettifeneb dna
,dnuora lla gnikool yerroT htiw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
liat ekil-elitper dna eson ekil-tnahpele ,smra sih
.edisni enola gnittis elttob retaw eht ta derats ehs sa
,sdne eht ta rehtegot kcab seceip eht pans dluow yeht neht dnA !sliat dna seson
,tcatnoc ekam ot desu skcits fo rebmun eht yb denimreted erew dedrawa stniop woh ekil
,llah eht nwod deklaw
!trops siht devol eH
.pu peek ot mih rof tluciffid t'nsaw ti tub
.dnuow eht nepoer eh tsel tsenoh eb ot lufraef
.raw karakS eht fo senil tnorf eht morf segami gniwohs saw leer swen a ,daetsnI
snailitper tuoba snoitseuq htiw reldA dereppep ehS
sffats gnol esoht ylneddus dna emag eht fo trats eht delangis taeb murd eht nehw taes sih ni depmuj yerroT
desirprus os saw eh yhw si hcihW
.ynoloc eht ot ytinummoc nailitper tsesolc eht ni tneduts egelloc a saw reldA
yerroT gninaom ,roop eht dna—mih derussa ak'naS tuB
,kcab mih guh ak'naS tlef eh nehT
.won mih ot gnitteg yllaer saw nihcru eht tcaf eht rof neeb t'ndah ti fi
.snoitidart dlo esoht fo esuaceb
,neht dootsrednu yerroT
.tliug lufhtuoy fo sthguoht ni gnimmiws llits ,nwod nihc
.tiaw t'ndluoc eh dna ,enog erew dad dna mom ecno ynoloc karakS eht ot mih ekat ot gniog saw reldA wenk eH
.retaeht eht ni dah dah ehs ecaf reh no kool emas taht gnivah
.emas eht gniod reh was eH .ak'naS ta
skarakS eht fo edis a gniees
,wonk t'ndid ehs dias ak'naS
si yrots s’yadot dna
,redro ot tahw aedi on dah yerroT
.ereht neeb reven dah eh
neeb dah ehs ylenol woh dna
ffats gnol eno rieht htiw ydaer doots yeht—
.elddim eht ni loop gib a htiw
.selacs sih no niks neila yrebbur eht gnileef
.edisni og ot deksa dna retaeht eivom a was yerroT
.knard tsuj dah eh retaw eht tuoba ak'naS deksa reldA
?gnihtemos htiw decal ti saW
etisbew s’kceramaS no dna
,rekceB .F.C yb ”skarakS eht htiW yaD A“
mih derussaer ak'naS
,eugnot naikarakS sih ni gnikaeps
,derevocer yerroT sA
,eurt saw dlot neeb dah eh
,roolf eht no yal yeht sa
.daeh sih gnuh eh dna
.flesreh tsicamrahpordyh a t'nsaw ehs gnieb
,lagelli saw kcits a tuohtiw bmil a htiw tcatnoc woh deton osla ehS
.sdoog yrd dna yrlewej
.rehtorb elttil sih teem dna dneirfyob reh ees ot regae
.emas eht lla gnizigolopa tub
,gnihtemos yerroT wohs yeht taht ak'naS ot detseggus reldA
.tenalp eht gnidavni yllautneve ymra karakS eht fo
,roloc-lluf ,egap ruof a ot
.daed eht morf retaw gnikat denoitnem ak'naS woh derebmemer yerroT
seitinummoc nailitper yna morf etarapes ecalpemos
,snaeco morf ti fo emos
,ti thgif ohw sreidlos eht dna
saw ti dnA .trops karakS a
repeekpohs rehtona yb dewollof saw ti dnA .did eh os
saw yerroT .devirra yeht erofeb taht tuoba yerroT dlot evah dluohs eh gniyas
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.eson ro dnah a htiw naht
,drawrof decaf yerroT
.evol ni llef yeht
,tsicamrahpordyh eht rehtar ro
,egelloc nailitper eht ni yduts ot noissimrep teg ot
.rehtorb elttil sih htiw yats ot dediced nailitper redlo eht tub
ynoloc eht ni yerroT mrah dluow karakS on taht wenk neve reldA
.sllaw eriw debrab eht nihtiw
,sdnah rieht dnuora yldipar meht gnivom
.efas saw ti derugif eh
.ylthgit yrev dleh eson reh
.edis rehtie no sevlehs fo sdnasuoht ebyam
.og ot dah eh ,hcamots sih tuoba gninaom
?retaw yllautca ton ti saW
.meht gnilbmessaer
.reilrae dias dah eh tahw ta
yerroT elttil dlot reldA
,no emac sthgil eht nehT
noituac hguone saw ereht tuB
tneminapmocca na sa nettirw yllanigiro saw yrots ehT
.ecnef eriw debrab eht hguorht
egaugnal nailitper lacol eht ta doog etiuq saw ehs ,erusaelp sih oT
.rehtorb elttil sih revo gnihctaw tfel saw tneduts egelloc eht
.sezis dna sepahs lla fo retaw fo selttob erew
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ynoloc eht ot gniog saw reldA yhw saw sihT
.sffats gnol htiw
.tsicamrahp a denoitnem ak'naS nehw deirrow elttil a saw eH
laer rof saw siht fi erus t'nsaw reldA
,tresed yrd a ni decalp eb ynoloc eht dednamed sredael eht taht
.sraey koot ynoloc eht gnihsilbatse rof snoitaitogen ehT
,taht retfa gnol ton dnA
,nageb emag eht erofeb taes sih ni gnimriuqs yllacitcarp saw nailitper redlo ehT .emosewa
.metsys ralos siht ot raw rieht gnirb dluow yeht gnitnih gnihton saw ereht dna
tnemnrevog detanimod-yratilim rieht htiw
.gnizama saw ytic ehT
,smurd fo elcric elohw a no gnidnuop
.retaeht eivom a t'nsaw ti ylnO
ksa ot htuom sih nepo ot tuoba saw eH
stniop erom drawa dluow
.snoitcejni dna sllip gnivig stsicamrahp ot desu saw eh—
,ecnelis eulb eht ni dneirflrig sih dloh rehtorb sih gniees
,tsicamrahp eht saw eh dias ak'naS tuB
.loop eht fo egde denoihsuc eht no smra rieht gnitser
.klat ot regae saw dna
raw fo semeht serolpxe krow sih ,eman eht morf sseug nac uoy sA .reddoFnonnaC
.dnatsrednu t'ndid yerroT taht drow a gnisu
,ti deciton ylerab dah yerroT
,rehtegot doirep hcnul yreve gnirahs
tsitra yrruf detnelat eht yb nward cimoc sseltxet
,sdor eht htiw rehto hcae ta gnigniws
redluohs sih revo ecnalg tsal a kool reldA
.enod dah eh tahw wonk t'ndid eh fi neve
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,rekceB .F.C yb
,kappik'oK fo nrael ot emoc dah eh stisiv reilrae sih nI
.dnuorgrednu gud saw ebut eht
.reh ot klat ot gnilliwnu ynam os htiw
.elbaknihtnu eb dluow snailitper gnireuqnoC
gnikoj saw rehtorb gib sih thguoht eH
,nmelos dna tnelis
.erots sih ni retaw fo lluf sepip eht lla htiw
.slamina fo seidob eht neve ro stnalp morf nward ti fo emos
.ecalkcen reh hcuot ot pu dehcaer ehs sa feirg fo wohs tnerappa na
,gnihtyreve no wolg rebmos a tsac thgil eulb eht
hguorht enog dah ak'naS troffe hcum woh denrael noos reldA
,luos evitisiuqni ylpeed A
nwohs gnieb saw tahw
tliug ni gninword saw edutitarg sih tuB
,deppots yalp dna tcatnoc gnikam
,tnaruatser eht ot teg ot edils a otno pmuj ot mih dlot reldA nehw
.pohs sih ni retaw eht gnildnah saw tsicamrahpordyh eht ylluferac woH
,rewsna ot yppah saw eh taht
.meht derewsna yltneitap ohw ,ak'naS ot snoitseuq fo stol deksa eh os
,secruos tnereffid morf emac lla dexim eh sretaw eht taht wenk ehs tuB
,tenalp eht fo trap rehtona ot stnerap s'reldA koot pirt ssenisub a nehW
,meht gnignarraer
,decneirepxe eh sgniht eht erahs ot detnaw eH
.ecalkcen a tuo gnidloh
.flesmih ecudortni ot sraef deleuf-romur yna kcab dehsup eh
,tsrif nwod dils ak'naS nehw tub
.erahs t'ndluow eh esimorp eht rednu
”skarakS eht htiW yaD A“
.modnaf eht ssorca lla morf saedi serutpac tcejbus daorb a hcus tub
tenalp rieht no seinoloc hsilbatse ot secar rehto dewolla dah snailitper eht elihW
,niap yreve htrow saw tI
.eno egral artxe na rof deksa yerroT nehw denrecnoc dekool ak'naS tuB
skarakS citelhta ,egral owt neht dna
.smhtyhr xelpmoc tuo gnidnuop lla
tuo emac dnabmra etihw a htiw karakS a
.erutluc karakS fo
.ecnerever hcus ni dleh gnieb erew retaw fo selttob eseht fo lla erehw
,ecivda s'rehtorb sih nO
nwod kcab evod neht
ekal gnilbbub eht gnilaever ssalg fo teehs a
,ytsat erew snihcrU
nailitper erom eno hcaet ot ,ehcatraeh ro
moor retawrednu na otni dils eerht lla sa
.lufwa tlef yerroT  .ssorg saw
.troppus nwo sih wohs ot
reldA dna ak'naS sa wollof ot esohc eH
,eerefer eht saw denialpxe ak'naS hcihw
noitseggus sih ta saw ehs truh woh ,yllanif dnA
.tcepxe ot tahw wonk t'ndid yltsenoh dna ynoloc eht ni enicidem rof kool ot dah reven dah eH
naht gninrael saw eh tahw tuoba erom gnikniht
liat eht htiw gnikirts woh dna
.mih decudortni evah ot yppah saw eh dna
.yad eno yrarbil ytisrevinu eht ni gniyduts namow karakS gnuoy a dnuof eh nehw
,hcnul teg ot tcirtsid gninid eht ot dedaeh yeht sA
.enutrof doog gnirb dluow elitper a ot stfig gnivig ,skarakS ynam rof dna ,deregnil llits snoitidart eht
.detcelloc sretaw rerar neve htiw
,tfig a saw ti taht
.was eh tahw eveileb t'ndluoc yerroT
.tuhs htuom sih tpek reldA
,mra s'rehto eht ot wolb mrif a dereviled rotitepmoc eno yllaniF
.2       .lla ta kool t'ndluow ak'naS taht deciton eh litnu pu—
ynoloc karakS eht retne ot nailitper a rof reisae hcum saw tI
,ecnatsid eht ni gniremmihs ynoloc eht htiW
daed eht morf retaw gniward taht
.sevitan nailitper fo tenalp a no ynoloc a tliub dah skarakS eht nehw nageb tI   .1   rekceB .F.C yb
,yas ot tahw wonk t'ndid eH
.htped taht fo elpmaxe na si yrots sihT
”skarakS eht htiW yaD A“
saw eson dna sdnah sih no sevolg rebbur gniraew karakS eht demussa dah eH
saw sihT.lla retfa
,sredro rieht ekat ot retaw eht rednu morf devirra retiaw ehT
.od ot tahw tsuj wonk ot demees eh
,ti knard yerroT retfa
,niaga dna niaga ti did eh taht hcum os ti deyojne eH
,oot ,nuf saw ti dna ,saw tI
:yojne esaelP   .trAtnaiveD ta
.dnif dluoc eh tahw ees ot tiaw t'ndluoc eh
.ecneidua eht ni skarakS deticxe tsom eht fo
pih reh dnuora mra na tup ot
.yldrawni dennirg reldA
.s'reldA fo lla derewsna ehs ecnis yllaicepse
.mih htiw derahs dah ehs lla
,retaw gnilkcirt dniheb gnimaelg thgil eulb
,evah dluohs ylekil eh naht regnol dehctaw eH
ssalg eht dehcuot sregnif wolley reH
,yxalag eht fo edis rehto eht no sdleifelttab no gnithgif erew seimra rieht ,revewoH
.tniop a gnidrawa eerefer eht
das saw ehs ees dluoc eh tub
.redluohs reh no dnah a gnittup
remmurd teerts a morf cisum htiw dellif saw ria ehT
.sromur esoht lla deleuf tahw
.hcamots eht no hguot eb dluoc
.wonk sdneirf ro ylimaf sih gnittel tuohtiw
.rebmahc eht deirub taht
,seceip rellams otni sffats rieht ekorb srotitepmoc owt eht ,noitca fo yrrulf a nI
,ak'naS sa doog sa erehwon ylniatrec dna
,ytivitca htiw deltsub ytic eht ,dnuora llA
,yawa dekool ak'naS
,lepahc retawrednu siht gnirevocsiD
.ssik ot detnaw ak'naS hcum woh tuo dnif ot ediug a sa ti esu dluoc eh ,lla retfA
noziroh eht rednu gnippid nus eht htiw ,emit sihT
,tenalp emoh rieht no srevir morf emos
ebut llams a fo saw sreh ylnO
,ecnatsid eht ni gnilkraps ynoloc eht htiW
,daer ot yerroT rof egnellahc a syawla erew seye kcalb ,egral reH
,retteb leef ak'naS ekam ot demees ti tuB
,emac yllanif yad eht nehW
reh ot nevig tfig rehtona neeb evah thgim ti gnirugif
,gnorw saw tahw gnidnatsrednu ton
.pleh dluoc eh taht—
.taht ta ecaf a edam yerroT
.retaw hguorht gniruc ni gnizilaiceps
.srevir gnitaolf esoht no nwot eht ssorca gnippiz
.mih deppots ecnelis eht nehw
seceip rieht gnilbmessaer retfa dnA
rebmulp fo dnik emos
.nees reve dah yerroT tnaruatser yna ekil t'nsaw sihT
ehcahcamots rehtehw
sisao na dliub ot
.tnemeticxe eht morf tsrub ylraen dah yerroT
,ecalptekram eht dnuora gniklaW
.gniraew llits saw eh ecalkcen eht ekil
,sderdnuh eht dna moor gnol eht nwod tsac
.raw yratenalpretni sseldne ylgnimees rieht dna
,ylraluger rehto hcae gniees nageb owt eht ylkciuq yreV
gnir eht otni deppets
,sepip lareves fo hcae morf retaw emos koot eH
.telecarb a mih gnidnah
ecno ta hcum oot tub
,gnihctaw peek dluoc reldA os tsicamrahp eht ot yerroT ekat ot dereffo dah ak'naS
,flesti no pu gnilruc eson gnol reh ,deffins ak'naS
,kcis os gnileef saw yerroT rooP
.ak'naS htiw eb ot ynoloc eht ot skaerb yduts sih gnikat ylteiuq
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,woleb steerts eht ees thgim eh depoh eh erehw ,ytic eht revo gnieb fo daetsnI
.flehs delaes-ssalg eno ta gnippots
.tnemom siht ni reh gnitroppus
,dnuora yaw rehto eht naht
.ti revo teg d'eH
,mih dniheb wodniw deniats eht morf ni demaerts thgiL
,ti ta derats dna tuo eno dekcip ak'naS yaw ehT
,slaes sa tsaf dna keels sa gnimmiws skarakS ees dluoc eh
.ak'naS decarbme reldA
ygolonhcet desab-retaw decnavda rieht desu noos dna smret eht ot deerga skarakS ehT
,hguoht ,sneila wolley eht ni tseretni na desserpxe rehtorb elttil sih nehW
,dezilanep tog liat erab sih htiw gel eht no tnenoppo sih dettaws ohw rotitepmoc eno dna
.ebut tset a ni rehtegot meht gnixim
,tsicamrahpordyh eht rof egarots saw siht ebyam thguoht yerroT
,elprup gninrut yks eht dna
.gnol os rof enoemos degguh d'eh emit tsal eht rebmemer t'ndluoc yerroT
flehs hcae edisni taht ees dluoc eh
,ti ekat dluohs eh dna
.4   .yrros ylurt saw eH