,ffo ro tes no ,dneirf tseb a ot evah I gniht tsesolc eht s’ehS
.elbat eht no kcab rotani-esreveR eht tes I ”.yako s’tahT“
,tuons ym fo trap reppu eht tsniaga spil sih sesserp yltneg eh dnA
”.uoy ot ti evag yeht esuaceb tsuj
”.gnihtoN“   .ksa I ”?tahW“
.ffuts lavihcra ecivres cilbup emitraw
.eno yad ecnis yspoT sa gnimrofrep neeb s’eitaK
.selbategev fo tol a tae I erehw wohs a od dluohs ew ebyam tub ,haeY“
yojne esaelP   .noertaP reh
.wohs rehtona s’taht dna
,ssik a em swolb dna yestruc a otni spid ehS   ”!spot eht er’uoY“
”.eman ym ...s’tahT“ .knilb I
.em ot kcab sllac dna spots ehs nehw rood eht ta s’ehS .niaga don I
,soediv fo stol hctaw I tub—
.won rof ,su neewteb
.eno ylno eht t’nerew I ylno fI
,ecno did I ebyam ,naem I
,dekab tsuj ehs ekac a htiw revo emoc ot gniog s’yspoT taht eveileb dluoc I
.syaw tnereffid dnasuoht a repap dlof dna stcejbo modnar pu wolb
.yltneg selkcuhc ttaM tub
.puc repap eht revo em ta worbeye na skriuq eH
.deneppah reven s’ti—
.flah retteb ym ykciR llac ylefas dluoc uoy kniht I“
.mrof yspoT tcefrep ni
.gurhs ot nrut ym s’ti woN
nethgirb noisserpxe sih hctaw I
?ecnereffid ega eht tuoba tahw tub“
”.hguoht ,yad txen eht sehciwdnas rof revo tfel hguone eb t’ndluoW“
,llaH retraC eeneR yb
.retaw rof elbat tfarc eht ot revo daeh eW
...tub ,on ,llew ,yakO
?trats neve I dluow erehw ;gnileef m’I tahw mih llet t’nac I
meht fo kniht I woh s’taht tuB .daD dna moM neve ro
.tes eht ot nwod rednaw I os
.gnihtyreve ...noisserpxe ,gnimit ,yrevileD
.si ecnamrofrep sih ,taerg t’nsi gnitirw eht nehw nevE
.depoh reve I gnihtyreve dna denigami reve I naht erom s’ti dna
.gnitrilf er’ew kniht I ?gnitrilf siht sI
.ereh devil yeht nehw kcab adniL dna seL yb pu gnuh erew semarf etihw rieht ni srolocretaw tcartsba eht nevE
.ykciR erew yllaer I hsiw I
,ytilanosrep rieht stcelfer emoh s’enoemos taht si noitatcepxe eht wonk I
”.gninrom siht dnatsswen eht no was I tahw kooL“   ”?tahW“
.kcitsyoj der dna sbonk sti htiw lortnoc etomer gib eht tuo ekat I neht dna
.sruoh lla ta dnuora gnimaor em ot desu s’maet ytiruces eht dna
,evac eht ni em dnuof srecudorp eht erofeb gnihtyna rebmemer ot elba gnieb ton htiw ecaep ym edam ecnis gnol ev’I
.elttil a selims eH
.gnitsurt dna ,etanoissapmoc dna ,eltneG
.emit nwo ruoy ot kcab uoy dnes ot em rof emit s’ti ,sdik ,lleW“
tsuj si siht oS“ .ffo strats eh
.em fo thguoht yeht woh s’tahT .elor rieht sa—
.retaw reh fo giws a sekat ehS
beW s’ettolrahC ,naem I
.werc eht fo rebmem a emaceb I
nirg I   ”!emit ni uoy eeS
.laer erew ti ylno fI
pots taht sdrow eht daer I neht dnA
,eltneg yrev s’eH“ .syas ttaM
* * *   …ruasonid devoleb eht rof
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sniatruc tod-aklop dna wodniw sti htiw
”.netae dna derethguals yllaretil eb ton ot
sdiolbat eht etipsed—
.enog ydaerla s’ehs
.tsixe t’nseod taht tius a ni yug a s’eH
dna sekac reyal-evlewt ekab dna srepmac ynit ni evil dna spooc nekcihc dliub elpoep hctaw I
,ti etah I ”...ereh tuB
flesym aidem laicos od t’nod I
snaej deyarf etirovaf sih ni llits
.llah eht nwod yaw eht lla mih hctaw I dna ,dezafnu
,og dluohs eh syas eh nehw ,retal sruoh dna
.no sthgil was dna tpircs s’worromot revo gniog saw I“ .sdda eitaK
,ffo sepol dna snrut eh nehT ”.suoregnaD“
.emit yreve pilc eciov emas eht gniyalp hsulp xeR ykciR gniklat eht yllautca m’I ekil
!RUASONID LAER A SI XER YKCIR
”?ykciR tuoba nerdlihc ot gnilaeppa os si kniht uoy od tahW“
.krad neeb syawla sah sdik rof ffuts tseb eht llA“
,ti ni ssenyhs a s’ereht dna
?ffuts rehto sih nees uoy t’nevaH“   ”...xeR“
!bulC .C.B eht dna xeR ykciR
”?niaga peels t’ndluoC
,doog si gnitirw eht nehw dnA
”.diolbat a tsuj s’tI .xaleR“
,tcefrep skool eH
pu tuhs tsuj I neht dnA
.ecno erow I setaks rellor fo riap a neve dna
.ylwols yawa gnikcab ,ffo em draw ot fi sa pu sdnah sih stup dna rorroh kcom ni em ta skool eh nehT
,woW“ .desserpmi skool eH   .don I
.repapswen a pu sdloh dna elims elttil a em sevig eH
,ecalp iahT a morf tuoekat redro eW
,yawa llup ot mih tcepxe I oS
.enog s’eh retfa gnol
wollof ot yrt I dna ,elbat eht dnuora yllufyalp skcud ttaM
?def-ssarg ekil eb taht dluow—
”.sriatspu tsuj evil I“   ”.erehwemos …mU
,daeh yspoT eht ffo sekat yletaidemmi eitaK ,em ot txeN
”.deraeppasid ylsuoiretsym evah snretni owt hguohtlA“
gniyrt retcarahc a tuoba saw
”.eman sih s’taht ,oN“
”.esol stluda ynam os taht
.rotca na eb ot gnidneterp tsuj s’eh ereH“
,niaga revo dna revo ”yrros m’I“ gniyas pots t’nac I dna ,eeffoc htiw dekaos si trihs nwod-nottub sih dna
.t’nseod eh tub ,revihs ot mih tcepxe I .t’nseod eh tub
,soediv esoht lla gniees m’I ,dnim ym nI
!em tae t’nod esaelP ...esaelp ,oN“
,)ekab ot sevol yspoT( stressed dna sekac fo stol
,ykciR eman eht evol I fi sa ton s’tI
,ereh srotca eht lla fO
,ekil skool noisserpxe ym tahw wonk t’nod I
.ti ta yako gniod m’I epoh I
4202 nocorhtnA ta evil uoy rof daer
tnemecalper elbissop no tnemmoc ot denilced…
.ffo dnuos eht htiw emit siht
uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
”.yawyna ,ma I naht retteB
”.tucriah a tog eH“
.retcarahc god a htiw yrteppup gniod ,nevahs-naelc
,no neeb s’eh swohs tnereffid eht tuoba seirots ynnuf eseht lla sllet eh dna
.slluks nrocinu gnimalf htiw detniap sekib dna stekcaj rehtael nagev htiw etelpmoc
”.lla s’tahT .snoitpo sih gnihgiew ...tsuj s’eH“
.etarebiled dna wols tnemevom hcae
era gnihtyna od nac ti eveileb yllaer ohw seno ylno ehT
.ruasonid a er’uoy swonk eno on
dna stnatsissa dna sreretac noillim a tuoba era ereht yltnatsni tub
,uoy fo trap emos fo noitcelfer a ykciR sI“
”.werc eht fo yna tae t’nod uoy os yad a taem war fo sdnuop derdnuh a uoy deef ew taht yas ot no seog tI“
,ssertnuH ysatnaf gninniw-drawA-ltoyóC eht fo rohtua
,llaH retraC eeneR yb
.tniap ynihs htiw
”.esimorp I ,enod er’ew sa noos sA .tcefreP“   ”.pu
,ylbissopmi si niks siH
”?thgir ,tuo mih ksa yllatot dluohs uoy wonk uoY“   ”.tey toN …mU“
revo gnol si weivretni eht ezilaer I litnu
tol a gninrael pu dnuow I
yawa klaw dna ,selacs ym piznu
.esrow sgniht gnikam tsuj s’ti esuaceb yaw sih gnicnalg pots I taht hcum os
.eeffoc kcalb fo puc a flesmih sruop ttaM
swalc eht ,hteet eht ,selacs ehT
”.ti hguorht teg nac yeht meht wohs tsuj eW
.xeR ykciR yllautca si ttaM
,em rof hcterts a eb d’tI .ylevitaerc ,saedi gnitseretni yllaer emos tog ev’yehT
eman a sah wohs siht no esle ydobyrevE“
,tespu kool t’nseod ttaM
,ekil leef dluow ti tahw rednow I
.rotani-esreveR xeR ehT   .emit eht lla
,yspoT dneirf spotarecirt ym ot ekacpuc knip dezisrevo na dnah I
.srecaR tekcoR no esuF
daer gnieb si yrots s'yadoT dna
.ylteiuq syas eh ”,haeY“
,tius a ni s’retroper ehT
meht dlot I oS .gniticxe s’tI
...pu yrd ll’taht oiduts ym ta kcab tneluccus a evah I
,retcarahc ehT .esruoc fo ,xeR ykciR tnaem eH
.lla ta ytilanosrep ym fo yna sah taht ereh hcum ton s’ereht tub
.tnemtrapa ym no nepo srood eht dna
dellac tolip a noitnem taht
.gnitsurt dna ,etanoissapmoc dna
”.sdik eht neve toN“
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.eitaK ,porp a s’eH
.namuh eb ot woh em thguat wohs s’dik a ,yllacisaB
.eet deveels-gnol kcalb a dna
neercs eht ta erats dna ereht tis I ,si ti revetahw tub ,rof gnikool m’I tahw wonk t’nod I
,lamina elbaniart a sa em fo aedi eht dekil yeht ebyam kniht I .ekilssenisub
”.retcarahc“ xeR ykciR eht fo ecaf namuh eht ,wohs yreve fo
.rotani-esreveR eht spat ehS
,daeh siht ffo ekat ot elba eb si od ot tnaw I lla won thgir dnA .em tsuJ
.lausu naht delsuot ylluftra erom skool riah krad siH
,eno siht ni regnuoy s’ttaM
,thgin taht peels t’nac I
,knil retfa knil wollof I ,enod s’ti nehW
,ebordraw otni og I
,neht dnah a tuo sehcaer eH
”.og ll’I neht dna ,nosaes eht tuo hsinif ll’I“
”?wonk uoy ,tuoba kniht ot gnihtemos ...tsuJ“
.elkraps seye sih dna
”.eman ym tsuj s’tI ?wonk I dluow woH .wonk t’nod I“
.em dehcuot ylerar srecudorp ehT
.shgual eh woN   ”.edis
wohemos tub ,eitaK ot kcab nrut I
.eman a evah t’ndid I“
.em gnieye s’eitaK   .lausu sa
,naem I .haeY“   ”?yllaeR“
.diarfa os eb ton ebyam oT
ot smacevil muirauqa morf gnihtyreve
.retteb neve s’eh
.moor gnivil tsilaminim a ekil skool tahw ni retroper enizagamswen a morf ssorca gnittis s’ttaM
,sretcarahc rehto eht htiw evaw dna
.yldeirruh syas ehs
.yadot enod er’ew retfA ?yako ,ti tuoba klat s’tel—s’teL“
,elbat eht fo egde eht stih liat ym tub—
.hcamots ym fo tip eht ni gnimossolb raef ,mih ta kcab ecnalg I
.nooccar yknarc a syalp eh erehw ,tseroF cigaM ehT fo sedosipe eerht hctaw I .reerac sih hguorht senots gnippiks
”,laiciffo ton s’tI“
,evac cigam ym ni ereh
.yas ot tahw aedi on evah I ”…tub ,wonk I“
”?yawyna ,gnimmargorp s’nerdlihc otni uoy tel reve yeht d’woH .elbirret er’uoY“
.did I tub ,eciton t’ndid I thguoht ylbaborp yeht os ,ti tuoba eltbus ytterp erew yehT
.sdaer enildaeh eht
,em rof ”larutan“ saw ti gnikniht ,no ylrae emos em gnideef deirt srecudorp ehT(
”.og dluohs eH“ .selor esoht lla
.reeteppup a eb ot gnidneterP
”.deciton t’ndah …I“
”.doog eb dluow netfO“
dlrow eht ta rednow fo esnes emas taht ,sah dlihc gnuoy a taht
.snaem ”nwod edispu“ tahw no nosaes tsal tnemges elohw a did eW
”eveileB-ekaM fo dniK
.kcilc gniht siht ekam dluohs yehT“
”,uoy deltrats I yrroS“
.yllanif yas I ”,taem war ekil neve t’nod I“
sseug I dna ,selitper yb desluper ro fo deracs era snamuh fo ytnelp
.snoitseuq ksa ot woH
.gniod s’eh tahw rettam on
.tes eht otno deklaw eh tnemom eht morf deciton I ,yllautcA
,yltneg selims eH
.tnaw ew revenehw rehto hcae ees nac ew ,wonk uoY“
”.did elpoep ynam toN“   .don I   .sksa eh
.gnihgual m’I ,syalp eh ohw rettam on
.gninrom txen eht eeffoc eht yb eitaK renroc I os ,ttaM ksa ot raeb t’nac I
”.eno em evag yeht oS .ti rebmemer t’ndluoc I tub
,floWcaM boR yb
.elims taht no dna—ttaM no pu-esolC
od ot desoppus s’ti tahw osla si ,ti tuoba kniht uoy nehw ,hcihW
werc eht yevrus ot snrut eH
.repsihw I ”,ti devol I“
.niaga ti od ot ekil d’I dnA
syad ylrae esoht ni tub ,yllis sdnuos tI   .eeyolpme nA
.tfel htaerb yna evah t’nod I ekil sleef ti hguoht neve ,tuo sdrow eht ecrof I ”.ereh detsaw s’eH
swen eht morf htob
,REKCOHS WOHS EIDDIK
”?srecaR tekcoR dekil uoY“
noisiced a sekam ykciR sa
.emag a yalp nac ew dna yb pots lliw ybanraB ebyam dna
?suoivbo taht ti sI
.seye sih hguorht sgniht ees ot yrt I ,tuo teg ew sA
”.eromyna ereh krow t’nod I fi nevE
,hcraes retfa hcraes yrt I
semitemoS .srecudorp ehT
,em ekil sdneirf evah oT
.gniog ekoj eht peek ot
etisbew dna stnuocca xeR ykciR eht seganam ohw rotanidrooc a tog s’wohs eht—
”?seidduB poT giB hctaw uoy did—
.srehto eht gnihctaw ,elbat eht tsniaga snael eH
”?xeR“   .sreloohcserp
.em ta kcab secnalg eH   .derad reve I fi
...sdik eerht dna dnabsuh a evah I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sdrow esoht fo yromem eht ta niaga srettiks traeh yM
sdaerht noissucsid elpuoc a ssorca nur I
…xeR ykciR retcarahc s’nerdlihc ralupop eht dniheb remrofrep…   .gnihtyreve
.sneppah ffuts dab wonk ydaerla sdiK“
.nwod gnihsarc semoc gniht elohw eht ti wonk I erofeb dna
em swollof ttaM ,yllaniF
.oga sraey ,wohs ’sdik rehtona morf tib senecs-eht-dniheb A
,timda attog uoy tub ,haeY“
.meht otni kcab efil ehtaerb ot sreenigne dna sreeteppup rof gnitiaw sniks eseht ,eugrom a ekil yliree sleef tI
”,erahs ew nehw dnA“   2 fo 1 traP
?mih oT    ?enoyreve oT
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,emit nwo ym ot kcab og oT
”?od ot gniog I ma tahW …tuB“
tsuj s’tI .rehtie ti etah t’nod I neht tub
,em ot txen ereh thgir
.senil ynam os debbulf reven ev’I
ssenlufyalp dna ecneconni
?eh t’ndiD   .em ton
,si ti tahw rettam on ,emit yrevE
.erus yleritne ton m’I tub ,smreg cihpromoporhtna lla era sretcarahc eht kniht I erehw enirambuS ylliS dellac gnihtemos rof tolip eht hctaw I
”,tey laiciffo t’nsi ti taht thgir saw eitaK“
,aet fo ytnelp s’ereht tub ,eeffoc knird t’nod I
gnikool s’eh ekil ,taorht ym ni hctac htaerb ym sekam ti tub ,tnatsni na ylno s’tI
.noisserpxe sih daer ot kciuq oot s’ti tub ,teem seye ruo tnatsni na roF
.mih ot yas ot tahw aedi on evah llits I tub
.gnidnats s’eh esolc woh morf dna
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
”?weivretni s’ttaM ees uoY“
ssem elohw eht ta erats dna
”.og ll’uoy—seod ti fi tuB“
.elpmis taht erew gnihtyreve hsiw I
.won thgir sa
.ezigolopa ot yako dna ,pleh rof ksa ot yako saw ti tahT
.riah atnegam ykips fo kcohs a gnilaever
.niaga sgurhs ehs yllaniF
gnag elcycrotom a nioj ot yawa snur ehs yad eno fi em esirprus t’ndluow ti ,flesreh seirrac ehs yaw eht htiw tub
”.tnaw uoy fi yspoT em llac nac uoy ,semit noillim a uoy dlot ev’I“
.aidem s’nerdlihc rof llib gnidnuf
.semutsoc gniraew snamuh tsuj t’nera ohw
,ti eveileb yllaer t’nod I
”.t’now ti ebyam ,neppah ll’ti ebyaM .ekil era sgniht eseht tahw wonk uoy dnA
no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,tiurf fo seceip tnaig era erehT .sevlehs dna
.swonk ydaerla eh hcihW
.od I tub ,neddus a fo lla evisnefed os leef I yhw erus ton m’I
,lleW“   .thgir tsuj enecs a nettog ev’ew nehw ees I taht
.doow detniap s’tI .esruoc fO .gnihtoN
desirprus era elpoep
,deirrow skool ttaM
.edis efas eht no eb ot tsuJ
,tenretnI eht nO   * * *   ”.xeR ,thgiN“
,moor porp eht ot revo detfird ev’I won yB    .sdik eht rof
”.uoy ssik dluoc I hsiw I“
,swonk oiduts siht edistuo enoyna sa raf sA
,tes eht ffo deklaw tsuj s’eh ekil skool ttaM tub
.smra ybbuts ym htiw nac I tseb eht gniod
,yas ot gnihtemos fo kniht ot yrt I
.yawyna ssenisub ym yllaer ton s’ti ,kooL“
.reh ta kool t’nod I
,nwod edir rotavele trohs a ylno s’ti os ,oiduts eht revo esuohtnep a s’tnemtrapa yM
,thgil mid eht nI
,elbatrofmoc dna ysae os ,dexaler os skool eH
.dias ehs tahw rebmemer I neht dna ,daeh ym ekahs I
.laid eht htiw selddif dna rotani-esreveR eht pu skcip ehS
...tub ,esruoc fo ,gniracnu toN
.erom semitemos dna
,ti noitnem taht sweivretni rehto dna selcitra era teg I lla tub ,swalc ym htiw ylwols ni sdrowyek gnikcep
.enim teem seye siH   ”.uoy ssim ll’I“
.tpek era stius eht erehw ot
,truh t’nsi dna kcab spmuj ttaM
,yas ot egaruoc eht dnif I rotavele eht ta dnats ew sa
,yllanif eganam I ”,haeY“
.esoht fo emos hguorht gnisworb trats I os
”eveileB-ekaM fo dniK tnereffiD A“
.sdnats ti erehw s’tahT“ .sgurhs eH
.noitseuq eht no gnidneped ,lacizziuq nrut dna netfos dna
,raey a sekat tohs hcae ekil sleef tI
doow tsuj lla s’ti ezilaer t’nod uoy ,pu ti kcip uoy litnu tub ,ynootrac dna yknulc s’ti—ti htiw boj taerg a did ,timA ,retsam porp ruO
.saw taht revenehw
”.mih rof epicer rekooc wols a ,ekil ,deen d’uoY .ygnirts oot eb d’eh ;trawetS ton ylbaborp ,naem I“
.siht ekil sthgin no
stiderc eht ni detsil reeteppup eht s’eH
,weivretni tsetal s’ttaM rof hcraes I thginoT
.laer erom neve skool ti
,rotavele eht otni
.seye s’eitaK ni rewsna eht ees ydaerla nac I tuB   ”?eurt ti sI“
.noitpecxe na t’nera seno gniklat net-toof-evif
”…ti lles dluoc yeht fi dna ,tolip eht od d’I
,ylenol ssel leef em sekam siht lla semitemoS
.draob no em tnaw yeht dna
…dnim ni evah yeht tahw tub
,sdrow dnif t’nac I tub—reh gnieb tsuj rof ,ecivda eht rof ,tnemegaruocne eht rof—
deracs dna yrgna dna das tahW
.og ot snrut dna nwod rotani-esreveR eht stup ehS ”.yawynA“
.stpircs xeR ykciR eht morf
.tser eht fo tuo reh pleh ot revo emoc sremutsoc ehT
ti fo ssenteews dna
.nihc dedraeb sih tsniaga regnif a spat eH ”?gnilbram dooG
,revo oediv eht trats I neht dna
,bulC .C.B eht erofeb reerac sih tuoba era snoitseuq eht fo tser ehT
”.nuf erom eb d’tI
.yas ot tahw aedi on evah I esuaceb ,don I
.stemmulp hcamots yM
.riah reh hguorht dnah a sgard eitaK   .ereht
.sdneirf ekam ot woH
morf enim fo sdneirf emos era erehT
.spilc yna dnif t’nac I tub ,ni osla saw eh taht nomiS ylpmiS
dna–efil sih egnahc lliw taht
,uoy evag yeht tahw ekat ot evah t’nod uoY“ .sesuap ehS
emas taht sah eH
.hcuoc eht no nwod tis ew neht dna ,senilced yletilop eh hcihw
.dias eb ot sah ti dna eurt s’ti tub ,ti etah I
.seunitnoc weivretni ehT
gnihtoos sleef syawla sdnah ym ni thgiew dna epahs sti tuoba gnihtemoS
* * *   .esle ydobemos sa
spuhcuot steg dna
.ekoj etavirp a s’ti ekil ,em ta yltcerid
.revo ekat ot enoemos dnif ll’yehT“
.niks htooms semoceb draeb demmirt-esolc eht erehw secalp eht ,ezag ym htiw waj sih fo enil eht ecart I
.noisiv larehpirep ym ni yawa gnippils eitaK fo erawa yleugav ,nrut I   ”.ton m’I“
.eeffoc eht fo tnecs eht htaeneb yaw sti sdniw engoloc sih fo ecips yklis tniaf ehT
,ereh s’eh llits dna
.nwo ym no ti eganam t’nac I ecnis ,elttob retaw ym no pac eht swercsnu eitaK
”...tuB .ti htiw looc m’I ,ti htiw looc er’uoy fI
taeh eht leef nac I dna
”.ytsat ytterp eb dluow werc eht fo emos
).yad yna erar muidem em evig tub
nairategev a s’ehS .ebyaM“   ”?yeliaB ebyaM“
”eveileB-ekaM fo dniK tnereffiD A“
llew os ti dootsrednu reven ev’I
.retcarahc on si ereht tpecxE
,aremac eht otni yltcerid gnikool ,hsinif I
”.uoy tpecxE .retcarahc a dna
.selacs ym revo gniregnil
,yhs tsomla ,elims elttil tahT
emit txen ni enuT
,moor eht ssorca gnikool s’eitaK   .enim lla—
.rotcerid eht htiw gnittahc s’ttaM erehw
,swalc ym revo hsurb spitregnif sih dna
.soediv gnitaroced emoh emos hctaw ot eton a ekam I
,tuc sllac rotcerid ehT
,em htiw serutnevda erom rof noos kcab uoy gnirb lliw
.snretni eht fo eno ta sdon dna su dnuora gniltsub
.wohs eht morf esarhphctac a no kcab llaf I os
”,flesmih ekildlihc yrev s’ykciR
fo dnik emos htiw ni deit eceip erutaef a
”.riaf smees ylnO“ .sgurhs ehS
”?sruoy ekil leef ti seoD“
.lworg dna swalc ym pu tup I   ”...yllautneve
,ot kcab gnimoc peek I porp eno ylno s’ereht tuB
.mraw yllufrednow
.drawrof kcitsyoj eht mals dna htaerb ym dloh I yllaniF
”.em fo esuaceb tsuj ereh kcuts eb t’ndluohs eh dnA“
,nwo ym no evil ot elba eb ot sdradnats namuh yb hguone dlo saw I dezilaer yeht ecnO
”?naem I tahw eeS“   .gnihtyreve fo
.yaw ruo gnidaeh s’ttaM   ”.kool ,hO“
.em ta stniop dna selims ttaM
dna llib gnidnuf eht tuoba elpuoc a neht dna
…tcejorp wen a ot nosaes siht fo dne eht ta no gnivom eb ll’eh sromur…
.petsrood rieht no deppord dah d’yeht dlihc gnuoy a tsom ta ro
,bonk eht tsiwt dna laid eht nrut I
.deziremsem ,hctaw dna no kcab dnuos eht nrut ot kcilc I
.yawyna epoh yzarc a htiw flesym dnif I ,syawla sa tub
”.eitaK ,hu—poT“ .pmuj I
.knird ot gnihtemos mih reffo ot hguone wonk I tsael tA
,ma I gnihtyreve ni ekat ,ezag sih ,hcuot tahT
.reh ekil erom eb dluoc I hsiw I yad yreve dna
”.yltsenoh ,ti no gnikrow ydaerla ylbaborp er’yehT
”?ecnamrofrep ruoy rof no ward uoy taht flesruoy fo tcepsa emos
.detroppus eb dluohs ti yhw
emoc ot tnaw uoy fI“
rotani-esreveR xeR ytsurt yM .yrrow t’nod tuB
,llaH retraC eeneR yb
tub ,oediv a kael ot enoemos rof gnitiaw sraey tneps ev’I
.rekihhctih flowerew
reh knaht ot tnaw I .yawyna shgual ehs tub ,ekoj diputs a s’tI
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.aremac eht ta gninnirg ,dnuora gninwolC
wohs yreve ni desu s’ti ecnis elbat a no tuo syats taht eno eht
,dne eht litnu hctaw I
snib citsalp fo swor eht gninnacs yldi
gnieb tuoba gnihtoos ylddo gnihtemos s’erehT
.won thgir ti gniod er’ew
taht denrael yllautneve I esruoc fO
.loohcs darg ni kcab morf rehto hcae wenk lla ew
.elbat eht no repap eht sessot eh sa elttil a nwod swols traeh yM ”.haeY .hO“
”.yspoT uoy llac I tahT ?riaf smees ylno ti ,naem uoy od tahW“
.yaw taht leef ot yako saw ti taht dna ,ekil tlef
.emutsoc a gniraew t’nsi ohw eno ylno eht m’I
.niatrecnu gnikool ,sdon dna swollaws eH
.ylenol os eb ton ebyam oT
.ytpme dna tnelis s’gnihtyreve nehw tes no
,eno trats ot ebyam ro—
,gnihton teef evif ykcots a s’ehS
,gninnips si daeh yM
”.regnuoy sraey noillim evif-ytxis ekil s’eH
”.tuo dnuof er’eW !ykciR ,yeH“
.detrats sah oediv rehtona dna
”?xeR ykciR uoy sllac ydobyreve taht uoy gub ti t’nseoD“
gniod su evah seussi aremac emos nehw yllaicepse
,adniL dna seL fo daetsni ,taht meht llac I nehw
.ni snael retroper ehT
.ot klat ot em ekil enoemos evah ot ecin eb dluow ti tub
.reverof–wohs eht
tnereffiD A“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT   .4202 nocorhtnA ta ecneidua evil a erofeb
.flesym fo etips ni hgual I
,wohs wen a rof saedi emos dnuora gnikcik er’yeht woN
”.enoyreve rof hguone syawla s’ereht“
,srecudorp evitucexe eht dna rotcerid eht tub ,laicremmoc yot dednetxe na yllacisab saw ti ,haey oS .tuc peed
saw eh nehw dnA .tnaillirb s’tI ...siseht sih morf leer omed ehT
,emoh laer ym si siht taht eveileb tsomla dluoc I
.semit evif segap eerht emas eht
”.netfo neve ebyaM
.rettulf tsehc ym sekam taht noitatiseh a
.ehtaerb neve t’nac I ,tnemom a roF
,aremac eht ta secnalg ttaM
,su dnuora srotinaj tnatsissa dna srotinaj