.swalc otni sdnah sih sekam eH
”?riahcleehw eht ni ,tah ruasonid eht ni eno eht ,tes eht ot emac lrig elttil taht nehw rebmemer uoy oD“
,em eb ot dneterp ll’ohw esle enoemos gniteem tuoba kniht I
,em htiw aet elbbep evah ot detnaw ehS“
.sih ni sdnah ym sekat dna elbat eht no aet sih stes eH
,spuorg sucof eht ot gnidrocca ,esuaceb
.no seog dna sdon ttaM dna
d’I taht ecneserp cilbup dna
.enola ,eciohc ruoy tsuj dna—eciohc ruoy eb ot sah ti kniht osla I tuB“
gnitsorf yarg ni derevoc sekac ypmul
.esle gnihtyna naht ereh ekac eht no desucof erom s’ykciR ekil smees tI
.gnitca fo dnik rehtona saw ti flesym dlot I ,emit eht tA …lleW“
erih ot emit fo ytnelp evah ll’yeht os ,worromot trawetS llet ll’I“
”.doog sdnuos ti tuB
.ni yrrac mih nees t’ndah I eno
”?emitemos klat dna nwod tis ot snalp ekam dluoc ew gnipoh saw I
…gnieb fo gnileef gnitaralihxe ,gniyfirret ,wen-dnarb
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
egnaro dna der fo hsalps a ,srolocretaw demarf-etihw esoht fo eno—
,wohs VT s’nerdlihc a no thgis nialp ni gnidih ruasonid a ,xeR ykciR
“’.yad elohw eht fo trap tseteews eht si ereh uoy gnivah tub
,ti sllac eitaK sa ”,tubed“ ym fo yad eht morf repapswen ni depparw s’tI
rehtraf gnitfird neeb evah I dna eh
thgin taht gniyas saw eitaK tahw teg I neddus a fo lla dnA   .em t’nsi tI
,ti deredisnoc neve reven ev’I tuB
siht no knurd-flah dna yddig ,niaga gnilggig m’I neht dnA
,ssertnuH ysatnaf gninniw-drawA-ltoyoC eht fo rohtua
,neeb sah ti ,sey yas nac I rO .ti ot desu m’I
dad yM .oga sraey evif yawa dessap moM“   ”.stnerap ruoY“
esle erehwon s’ereht
enilno og I yllaniF
.enola ereht tuo gniog ton m’I wonk I tsael ta tub
.kaeuqs a ekil erom
.erofeb enil a denoitseuq reven ev’I
”.rotani-esreveR ehT“
.em ta serats enoyrevE
,ni ti sekat eh sa seye sih ni gnihtemos s’ereht ,llitS
namotto yelsiap emas eht tsap gnillorcs retfA
.ssenisub siht tuoba dekil ev’I gnihtemos s’taht ,hguoht ,sseug I“
,puc eht morf plug a sekat ,sgurhs ehS ”.ssel ro
”?boj eht ekat uoy d’yhW ...ttaM“
.edisni reh evaw dna srood rotavele eht nepo I
.tsop ni dedda eb ot
.t’nsi ti esuaceB
,llaH retraC eeneR yb ”eveileB-ekaM fo
”,snikliW nayR“ ...ebyam rO
laer erew uoY“   .tnetni dna tfos
elggig em sekam hcihw ,ruasonnaryt
.oot ,elkcuhc I dna ,elttil a shgual eH ”?wonk uoy ,rrraR“
.yawa og yromem eht ekam ot gniog s’ti ekil seye ym esolc tsuj I
.elbat eeffoc eht no ssalg eniw ytpme sih stes ttaM   .ma I ohw fo yenruoj eht fo trap s’taht esle gnihtemoS
em dnuora wohs eht tliub yeht dias syawla yeht ,neht tuB .meht ot tcejorp
”.flesruoy sediseb esle ydobyna rof ro
.ti sesu eitaK tub ydobon fi neve
.ssarb oiduts eht dna ,srecudorp wohs eht ,ttaM dna em—
,em rof ti od ot uoy tnaw t’nod I
.lla ta gniyrt neve tuohtiw dneirf doog a hcus ekam ot deganam I woh gnirednow
.nehctik eht ni gnitaeh retaw teg I dna
m’I sseug I ,esac taht nI“
fo gnileef eht ,tnemom a rof ti enigami I
.gniviler s’eh seiromem tahw rednow I dna
.wohs eht fo syad tsrif eht tuoba gnikniht
...fo level a koot taht eveileb-ekam fo dnik tnereffid A
,kcolc eht ta kool I
”.evac eht nI .sekac kcor dna
,retal syad wef a semoc
”.ekam ot desu amdnarg taerg-taerg-taerg ekil tsuJ“   ”!sekac kcoR“
.llaw ym no evah dluohs I ,ezilaer I ,esle gnihtemos s’tI
,ta dnats ot wodniw a rof gnihsiw m’I ylnedduS
,wonk ot tnaw I esle gnihtemos s’ereht won dnA   ”.tfig a
.selims ttaM    ”…naem I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sseug I ,uoy ot taht od lliw ”sretnuh yhport“ sdrow ehT(
.ti sees eh nehw eniw sih no sekohc ttaM
elohw eht fi ,dneirf a em llac dna em htiw krow nac eitaK fi dnA   .em m’I
,deracs eb ot detcepxe I
fo elttil a em sdnimer
,srettam taht gniht ylno eht ,hturt elohw eht
”...tub ,erew uoy derugif
”.syawlA“ .repsihw I
.sdik laer htiw ffuts teerts-eht-no emos gnidulcni
eno ylno eht osla s’ehs tub ,eb ot retsis gib a
,rehtona retfa eno hctaw eW
si tnemtrapa na gnidnif
”.syug ,retal uoy hctaC“
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.emit nwo ruoy ot kcab uoy dnes ot em rof emit s’ti ,sdik ,lleW“
”...dna swalc dna hteeT .yltsenoh
.sdnoces evlewt yreve tuoba gnos a s’ereht ekil sleef ti ,gnol setunim 42 ylno s’wohs eht ecnis dna
.oga sraey enizagam a fo tuo tuc I adniL dna seL fo erutcip a
,retal shtnom yad eht rebmemer I dnA
.erew uoy tahW .erew uoy ohw
.ti tup ot woh fo kniht ot yrt I ”.yllaer toN“
”.tuoekats a no m’I .hhhS“
sweivretni od ll’ohw
.truh t’nerew sgnileef reh erus gnikam ,reh
.xob gnikcap eht nepo tuc ot walc a esu dna repap eht ffo raet I
eroM“   ”?thgin lla ereh neeb ev’uoY“
”.elcnu doog a er’uoy teb I“
,setis tnereffid eerht no
...gnikniht tsuj saw I“
”.doog sdnuos toh gnihtyna ,won thgiR“   ”?aet ekil uoy oD“
?em hcuot ot raeb nac ohw eno ylno eht s’ttaM fi tahW
,worromot ecnerefnoc sserp taht rof ydaer raen erehwyna leef t’nod I
ta gnikool ,snoitpo eht hguorht llorcs I sruoh eerht txen eht roF .setis gnihsinruf emoh gnisworb trats dna
.erehwemos ereh reward a ni s’tI
,yeH“ .nwod gum reh stup eitaK   .hcum oot s’ti
.oot ,secnereffid ebordraw emos era erehT
rrrar eht neeb reven ev’I
.nwod sgum eht gnittes ,yas I ”,aet elbbep yna evah t’nod I yrroS“
.taht evol ll’ytiruceS“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.slatsyrc ragus htiw delknirps dna
.daeh sih gnikahs ydaerla s’eH
,lufroloc s’ti fo emos ,ytterp s’ti fo emoS
...sa secnaraeppa cilbup ot desu gnitteg llits m’I
.nwotpu yrekab eht morf xob knip a htiw gnihcaorppa ttaM ees ot reh tsap ecnalg I ”...yllautcA“
,alag emos rof pu desserd lla
.erehwyna aremac no ees reven I eno ,teews dna tfos dna nepo
.spot ,setunim net
”.gnola emoc ot tnaw uoy fi ,etarbelec ot ecalp s’trawetS ot gniog era su fo hcnub A“
.siht ekil snoitautis ni hsulb snamuH
,eno nosaes rof gnihcraes dna retupmoc eht no gninrut pu dniw I
.swollaws dna daeh sih sekahs eH
.slasraeher hguorht enecs yb enecs em gnihcaoc eitaK ,won ,rebmemer I
.uoy fo duorp m’I ,tahw rettam on ,lleW“   ”.tseggib ehT“
”—tub ,yltcaxe ,erac t’ndid
.evarb sleef reve ydoboN“
dedaerd ev’I tnemom ehT
.pu dne thgim uoy erehw wonk t’nod uoY
talps dna hsarc citamard
?siht wonk I t’ndluohS
yteltbus dna tcat
s’tahT‘ ...ekil gnihtemos ebyam oS
,nosrep rehto emos gnihctaw
,emit tsaL   .noertaP reh no
.evol yllaer reve dluoc ydobon taht ruasonid gniklat ylenol driew roop eht rof yrros gnileef
.sthguoht ym raeh nac eh fi sa shgis ttaM   ).sseug
.taht htiw luferac eb retteB“
.laer era hteet dna swalc eht wonk yeht taht won
”.ti od dluohs I kniht llits uoy oS“
.dloc enog s’aet yM    ”?em htiw uoY“
,em ta gnizag s’eh
.krow retfa aet gnivah fo tibah eht otni nettog evah I dna ttaM
,llaH retraC eeneR yb ”eveileB-ekaM fo dniK tnereffiD A“
”?ecalp tsrif eht ni yrots revoc a tsuj saw taht
.yalp kcilc I erofeb emit gnol a rof neercs eht ta erats I dna
.llew dne nac siht yaw on s’erehT ?diputs os eb I nac woH
”.nosrep a erew uoY .neht em ot
retal em htiw tem yehT“
”.dloc retteb yna t’nsi ti dna ,oga sruoh eerht eeffoc ysuol saw sihT .haG“ .ecaf a sekam dna
”.em ot dna ,meht oT
thgin taht emit fo tol a dneps I
teehs llac eht no xeR nayR sa
.uoy ni was I rednow taht gnitcetorp tuoba saw tI
”?neht dnA“   ”.uoy tem I litnU
,eno sekat eH ”?sekab eitaK“
.pu ti tes ot gnilbmarcs gniretac tnes uoy dnA“
.ffo sesae gnikahs ehT ”.dooG“   ”?taht s’woH“
.syad rof em dekcerw taht dna ,em morf yawa dik reh dellup rehtom a emit enO
,erehwyna stnemges od nac I os
.enim lla si kniht ot ekil I taht enO
4202 nocorhtnA ta evil uoy rof daer
,revocsid ot ykciR rof erom s’ereht tuB
.scitirc dna sdik htob fo noitnetta eht thguac s’taht IGC dna yrteppup lanoitidart fo xim latnemirepxe na
.uoy saw tahT .sevlehs yot eht dna sexob eciuj eht morf xeR ykciR eht t’nsaw tahT
“’.em eb ot gniog s’ohw eno eht er’uoY‘“
.rehtegot ti yas eW
.gniyrt fo kcal rof ton s’ti tub ,em dnuora smra reh teg t’nac ehS
,ecalp otni ylmrif tub ylteiuq stif meht fo eno
.skaeps eh erofeb stnemom wef a rof eniw sih otni sezag eH
a fo tros ...saw I kniht I“
,driew skool tsuj hcihw ,llirf reh ot dehcatta sgnirrae ylgnad sah yspoT
”.meht fo yna gnikat t’nerew uoy dna
,ecneirepxe wen dna thguoht wen yreve ,noitasrevnoc yreve ,wohs yreve htiw
,shtnom xis tsal eht fo soahc eht retfa
.dnah ym tuo dloh dna
tuo semoc drow eht tub ,evisiced dnuos ot tnaw I   ”?ohW“ .snworf eH
,llaH retraC eeneR yb ”eveileB-ekaM fo
,riah sih fo tnecs eht ni gnihtaerb
)hteet on ,ylluferac( elims I
...saw tI .ronoh na saw tI .efas uoy gnipeek ,efas ti gnipeeK
.gnikahs m’I esuaceb nwod gum ym tes ot evah I
.gnos emeht eht fo elgnij ycnuob gnitrofmoc eht dna ,neercs eht no sroloc thgirb eht ,eugolaid eht fo smhtyhr eht ni flesym esol I dna
.niaga mih dnuora flesym parw dna
,hcuoc eht ot kcab emoc
.sdda eh ”,tsrif uoy llet ot detnaw I“    .ma I ekil
llaw eht ta erats dna neercs eht morf pu kool I
,thgindim ot esolc ,yllanif tub
”?yad taht rebmemer uoy oD“
”?huh ,worromot yad giB“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.uoy knahT .tcefrep s’tI“
.tuc sllac rotcerid eht dna
”?srecaR tekcoR nees reve uoy evaH“
,slaid dna sbonk eht htiw gniht ym od I   ”!emit ni uoy eeS
,elkraps seye siH
.alpooH doowylloH htiw ,nosmohT eihpoS“
”?...yllautcA“ .yas I ”,mU“
.emutsoc fo tuo s’ehs sa noos sa em dnuora smra reh sworht eitaK   .gnitnuoc dna
.pal ym ni xob eht stes eh sa em ta kcab gnikool si ecaf suoixna ylthgils nwo ym os
.potpal ym no sllaf ezag ym neht dna
”.boj eht rof tcefrep er’uoy kniht I“
?gniht em-ton ,dnalb eno siht fo ecalp ni
tuoba denrecnoc erom eb d’eh kniht I
sretcarahc niam eht lla ecudortni ot esucxe na tsuj yltsom si yrots ehT
,peelsa llits s’ehS
”.thginot ynapmoc emos deen thgim uoy thguohT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
* * *   ”.yap rehtar d’yeht eno hcihw
).taem war ekil neve t’nod I ,dias I ekiL(
...a evah rehtar d’uoy derugif I“
,niaga yas I ”,nayR“
.laer m’I dna ,em s’tI
,ylluferac ti yas I ”.nayR“   .sega rof
.tnuoc t’ndluow ti ,did yeht fI
.stseug gnivah peek ot gniog m’I fi rekameeffoc a yub I dluohs I esoppus I
,em decudortni s’L eht neht dnA“ .epyt
.emit taht gnikat roF
.divil saw trawetS
.ysub oot htob er’ew ;won yad yreve rehto hcae ees t’nod eW
.ekoj a saw gniht elohw eht thguoht taht em fo trap llits saw erehT“
,rood eht raen egakcap a pu skcip
.reh ot txen elbat eht no eeffoc tuoekat fo puc tnaig a s’ereht dna ,worht eceelf a ni depparw s’ehS
.seod reve ydobyna sa hcum sa tsael ta
.niks ym otni bmilc nac yeht fi sa
eb ti nac woH .llec yM .yrautcnas yM .em tub tnemtrapa ym otni emac eno on ,sraey ynam os roF   ”.yaw siht thgiR“
”.eromyna ti deen t’now yeht dias sporP“ .sgurhs eH
.eromyna ecalp eht fo ytimynona eht dnats ot elbanu
.erew uoy laiceps woh wenk I nehw s’taht dnA
.ssik a su swolb ehS
.emas eht erew yllaer ew ,neht kcab ebyaM  .sdneirf sih
,knarp etarobale gib emoS
.em ta sgan enil taht tub
”.retspmuD egatniv a fo tuo deluah ylbaborP !teb I“
—em evol dna ,ma I sa em ees nac ttaM fI
,nwod meht gniworran dna
.ti ees ot yrruh on ni m’I tub
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb
.neddih flesruoy gnipeek ot tsoc a s’ereht dnA
—sraey rof em htiw edis yb edis eb nac werc dna tsac
.pu evig dna lworg I
,elbat edis a no emarf erutcip revlis eht no neht sllaf ezag siH
.won rebmemer I   ”—dias uoy dna
a htiw ,ykciR rof edam ehs ekac yadhtrib tnaig eht deppord tsuj
,ti ot desu teg ot dah ev’I .desu neeb sah
yeht taht ton s’ti oS
.mir eht revo em seiduts dna pis a sekat ehS ”.retteb hcuM“
.tnemom a retfa ylteiuq skaeps eH
,ksa ot driew sleef tI   ”?pleh I nac woH
.pu eb d’uoy derugif I .uoY“
.liated ytiruces no elpoep erom wef a dna snoituacerp elbanosaer
gninrut ,mih ot txen flesym kcut I dna
dniK tnereffiD A“yojne esaelP
.nwo ym no lla ,gnisoohc ,gnihgiew ,gnihcraes
].tidE tidE tidE .og ew ereh dna …sdrow ni ti od t’nod uoy sa gnol sa uoy sevom yrots eht sa tcaer esaelp ,tidE tidE tidE htiw senil debbulf kram ll’I ,gnidaer eht od ll’I ,erofeb sa ,woN[   .4202 nocorhtnA ta ecneidua evil a erofeb daer gnieb si yrots s'yadoT dna
.rehtegot owt uoy ees ot doog os s’tI“
.aremac eht fo edis siht morf ton ,tolip ruo dehctaw reven ev’I yllautca ,llew—
emit siht citsaisuhtne yllaicepse era selims ehT
,erofeb ti enod reven ev’I
”.bulC .C.B eht teeM“ dellac s’edosipe eht ,lla retfa—
.em wonk ot teg ot sraey eht revo troffe yna edam s’ohw
I ytriht-owt dnuora erehwemoS
,daeh ym ekahs I yllaniF
.revetahw ro ’,tseb ym od ll’I ,lleW‘ ,dias I dnA“
.ti eveileb etiuq t’nac llits I esuaceb
rof gnihcraes neeb ev’uoy eceip elzzup taht gnidnif ekil
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
.enecs gninepo eht hguorht yaw ym egnirc I
,kciht nezod a flah era edisnI
,rulb a era syad ylrae esoht fo ynam os tub ,yrt I
dniK tnereffiD A“
;hsinif ot woh wonk neve t’nod I ”…fi tahW“
.nus a ot noom a morf seog neercs ym fo renroc eht ni noci rehtaew eht ,ti wonk I erofeB
”.ti no eldnah doog a evah yeht ekil sdnuos tI
,ekat eht hsinif eW
stsil gnikam emit emos dna gnillorcs fo tol a sekat tI
ni tolip ruo dehctaw t’nevah I
detsil yllanif m’I yad emas yrev eht
.swehc dnA .swehc dnA .swehc dna
,smoor ym hguorht ylsseltser ecap I ,thgin tahT     2 fo 2 traP
,elims fo dnik wen a—
.eniw fo pis a sekat eH
”.evarb tlef I hsiw I“
.ti fo etunim yreve gnivol s’eh dna ,detnaw eh egnellahc eht tsuj s’tI
,elbat eht no ti tup I   ”.nehw rO
.yppah os kool dik a nees reven ev’I“   ”.t’ndid ehS
.sruoh eerht deyats yehT
”?sretsop edam yehT“
,sih ni sdnah ym sekat eH
denigami syawla I tahw ekil s’ehS
,resolc ni nael I ”.swodniW“
.erofeb morf gnihtyna rebmemer t’nod I“
yug ecin a tsuj ,ytip ylno si—
peels no pu evig
“’?em edisni teg uoy nehw truh ti lliW‘“
.wohs sdrawa na ebyam
,evael ot dah yeht taht stnih pord ot gniyrt tpek eH
.)ebyam ,llaw ym rof esle gnihtemos(
”.nosaes tsrif eht rof sedosipe neT
,ti spsalc ehS
”.epicer ylimaf tneicnA“
,wonk t’nod I ,ekil skool erutuf eht tahW
sruoh rof stsal gniteem ehT   * * *   ”.eM“
,em htiw serutnevda erom rof noos kcab uoy gnirb lliw rotani-esreveR xeR ytsurt ym—yrrow t’nod tuB
.tnuts yticilbup a ro xaoh a s’ti kniht ll’ohw elpoep fo ytnelp eb ll’ereht ,dias yeht ekil dnA“
.trapa rehtraf dna
tcaer thgim elpoep woh erus reven m’I tub ,xeR ykciR sa sdworc ni gnieb melborp a dah reven I .flesym ,llew
.ti fo kniht I retfa setunim wef a rof ylballortnocnu
os tsilyalp tneibma na pu deuc ev’I emit sihT
?ni eitaK tel reven ev’I taht
.deirrow skool eH ”?yR“
.tolip eht thguob oiduts ehT …oS“
mih llet dna sih revo dnah ym tser I ,daetsnI
.taht ot yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I   ”.flesruoy yb
”.daetsni sekac kcor evah tsuj s’teL
tsrow ta dna ,cilbup ni suoixna tib a teg I tseb ta tub
.riaf si siht fo enoN .riaf t’nsi tI
,ecaf reh revo rekcilf thgil s’neercs eht hctaw I dna
.sseltniop leef yeht mid os wolg taht spmal elttil ,sevlehskoob
.eniw sih fo pis rehtona sekat eH
.NOITAGITSEVNI .SUOREGNAD .REKCOHS
eno tsrif eht s’ttaM ,niaga nehT
.ylteiuq yas I ”,yeliR“
.sdon dna erutcip eht ta kcab skool eH
.ksa I ”?uoy tuoba tahW“
.yR ,flesruoy ylluf gnieb ot tsoc a s’erehT“
ekil sdrow desu taht eno eht
,nwot ni ereh retsis a evah I tuB
.cisum on ro cisum ,won rehto hcae htiw elbatrofmoc erom tsuj er’ew ebyam rO
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT.eb rehtar d’I
.kraP cissaruJ morf seno eht dnA
sleef fo tros llits ti tuB
.mih tuoba sleef eh woh rats-oc namuh sih dlot yllanif
.syad fo ytnelp dah eW“ .gurhs I
,rehtom s’yeliR morf
”.ydaerla tsil trohs a tog ylbaborp ev’yeht ,dnuora sromur eht lla htiW .enoemos
.flesym llet I ,ereh tratS
”.redro laiceps a ni tup I ,sediseB
erehw ,roolf eht ta nwod kool I ,gnimlif gnirud yad txen ehT   * * *   .flesym
.od srotca tahw fo trap s’tI .laed gib on ,emit eht lla ti seod esle ydobyrevE
…noitatiseh yna ees I fI
…uoy did nehw dnA“
,sgur ,sesav ,tra demarf
”.evarb eb ot deracs eb attog uoY
.ytic eht ta tuo kool ot
”.ylimaf ekil s’ti ...werc doog a htiw ,wohs doog A
.hcum klat t’nod ...I dna
.elbuort eht lla ot og d’yeht
.etis eman-ybab a pu llac dna ,bat wen a nepo
.yad tsrif yM .yad wen A
.tes eht ot nwod daeh ot ediced dna
,sretcarahc eht lla fo egalloc eht dna
,ekac ecin a saw tI .yspoT ,yako
.noitcelfni ,gnisarhp ,gnimit—
.ylteiuq sa tsuj ,yas I
,raf os deneppah s’dab ylurt gnihtoN
”—dias uoy neht dnA
”,eitaK ,spot eht er’uoY“
no ylrae dexa tog hcihw ,kcen ym dnuora annadnab wolley a gniraew m’I dna
.em neve ton s’ti ekil s’tI
.flesym htiw yrgna tsomla leef I
”.gnitoohs fo syad owt dniheb erew ew ,revo lla saw ti emit eht yB
si ediced ot sah enoyreve tahW
ekil sleef tahw rof kniht I
ogol srecaR tekcoR eht
.erehwemos ti rof flehs laiceps a ebyam ,emoh wen ym ni
,yllautneve dluow I ebyam thguoht yehT
,srettam taht lla si won thgiR
.ybbol eht ni riahc a morf pu skool eitaK ,nepo srood rotavele eht sa noos sA
annadnab ym gnihctaw ,ereht tis I sA
,ni setib
oiduts eht ta eton a tog ew nehw
ti tcaf ni dna ,thgir sdnuos tI .ti gnitset
”.nosrep trams yrev a toN“
”.evarb yllaer ,yllaer
!bulC .C.B eht dna xeR ykciR
.noitarbelec teiuq
ekil rof ereh eb ot desoppus erew yehT“ .sdon eH
,sehsinif eh ”,no neht morf dnA“
”.tseb eht m’I neht ,elcnu doog a m’I snaem efil sih fo hcni na nihtiw mih gniliops fI“ .shgual eH
.yllautneve eno deen ll’I hguoht ,tey eman tsal oN .gnidiced
.liat ym rof wolla ot tib a syawedis
,mih rof tnaw I tahw si siht taht flesym dnimer ot yrt I
.spil reh ot regnif a stup ehS   ”?eitaK“
.ytpme ssel leef secnelis eht
.llaw eht no dehsalps puos otamot fo lwob a ekil skool taht
:seman tuoba eitaK ot gniklat sa gnileef fo dnik emas eht em sevig lla ti tub
.yako eb ll’tI .ereh m’I
.ssalg eniw ym ta nwod kool I
yhw aedi on dah I fi neve
”.stnerap ton ,srecudorp sA“
era esohT .evac sih s’tahT
.deen uoy tahw rof gniksa tuoba wohs elohw a did ew tub
s’ti tub ,seikooc s’eitaK fo eno nwod ekohc I
,ereh erew hsiw I od tahW
”.snosaer htob roF
,neht tnereffid elttil a saw yspoT woh nettogrof d’I dna ,oot neercs eht no s’ehs woN
* * *    .tuc ew retfa pu-sbmuht a em evig eitaK evah ot hguone s’ti tub
.eb ot mih pleh nac evol wen siht evarb woh tsuj tuoba dna flesmih tuoba
rehtegot ereh su fo owt eht ,em ot txen hcuoc eht no mih ,siht fo lla ,won thgir ,siht—siht taht yrrow dna
”.hguoht ,laed gib a ton s’tI“ .wollaws I
”.rinevuos a sa ti ekil thgim uoy thguohT“
...llitS   .demlehwrevo
.mih gnisol ton m’I .gnihtyna gnisol ton m’I flesym dnimer ot yrt I
.emit ni emoc nac taht tuB
,otni teg nac I enihcam emit a em gnivig er’yeht nosaes txeN .don I
”.wonk I nosrep tsevarb eht yllaiciffo er’uoY
neve tub ,reh htiw og ot stnaw em fo traP
,emit siht lla ereh pu ,neeb evah tsum ti ylenol woh tuoba thguoht reven I“
.ssalg eniw sih fo mir eht gnola regnif a secart eH
.ecaps morf ti ees ylbaborp nac yeht ylthgirb os su ta gnimaeb s’eitaK   ”.snalp evah eW“
,won wohs wen a no s’ttaM dna ,esruoc fo ,sweivretni erom gniod m’I
,nayR drawot dna ykciR morf yawa pets ynit rehtona tsuj s’tI
.eludehcs ffo gnihtyreve werhT
.aedi eht tog tsrif I tnatsni taht ni tlef I yaw eht
.evarb dna yllufecaep
.oga emit gnol a wonk ot desu ebyam I ydobemos
.em s’ti ,eihpoS ,seY
...neeb s’ti eveileb ot draH“
.thguoht I tahw s’tahT“   ”.egnellahc A“
”.laer lla ti gnikam roF
.kcab emoc dluow seceip dna stib ebyam taht
.lrigloohcs s05‘ fo dnik emos m’I ekil ,eman tsal s’ttaM
.yad taht rebmemer I
ekil s’ti ,cisum eht ot yldrawkwa gnippob fles de-
.gninnirg pots t’nac I dna
.ylhsipeehs selims ttaM
.hguone esolc s’gnileejraD“
”.sekac kcor era yeht ebyam“ ,yllanif yas I ”,thguoht dnoces nO“
.gnihgual htob er’ew neht dna ,enim teem seye siH
,dias dna deil evah thgim I ,emit gnol a roF
.ttaM ta ecnalg I
?ma I ohw wonk I t’ndluohS
selims eh neht dna
,tnemtrapa siht nees reve s’ohw
.nosaes tsrif eht fo esruoc eht revo nwod reh denot eitaK .ylggig dna repyh erom
”?stnerap ruoy rebmemer uoy oD“    .don I
.kcis tog ehs erofeb nekat
.pu gnisnet ydaerla m’I ,ti yas I sa nevE ”?guh a …ebyaM“
”.erih dluohs yeht ohw wonk I kniht I“ .plug a ekat I
.reh llet I ”,uoy teem ot erusaelp a s’tI“
.repsihw a ot eciov ym pord I ”.hO“
,yakO( .etius letoh a ekil sleef tI
,rorret dna tnemeticxe dna esirprus ym ot
”.swodniw fo stoL“ .niks sih
yaw a nI .gnihtyreve ot ,nepo ...os erew uoY“
”,flah a dna eerhT“   ”?sraey ruof ,tahw
syawla I ,naem I ?esolc uoy ereW“
.T.E morf stsitneics eht rebmemer I .og sgniht eseht woh wonk I   .DERUTPAC
.sdik eht ni ees I tahw srorrim taht rednow gninediw ,wols a tsuj
.sehcterts dna snirg ehS
,edosipe htdnasuoht-eno ruo s’ti—
.boj rehtona tsuj t’nsaw ti“
.boj siht naem I ,oN“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”—elttil a hcterts ot emit ekil sleef
...tuoba em dlot d’yehT
,edisni dekcut yeliR fo erutcip a saw erehT
.erutnevda na ekil leef ot hguone ronim
.ekil I tahw wonk neve t’nod I ,gnol os rof
.smra trohs ym htiw nac I sa hcum sa kcab reh guh I   ”!erom ynam dnA“
.drawretfa aet revo sesum ttaM ”,esruoc fo ,dezingocer gnieb tuohtiw teerts eht nwod klaw ot elba eb t’now llits uoY“
.yldesoppus ,emutsoc fo tuo saw I nehw—
,retal dib gninepo na dna sdrowyek wef A
,oot peelsa llaf I sseug I yllautneve dna ,em ot txen pu delruc peelsa sllaf eitaK
.sekac kcor fo xob ytpme yltsom eht dna sexob tuoekat ytpme yb dednuorrus
snaem tsuj taht tuB
”…lleW“   ”?txen tahW .yakO“
”.pu dewohs reve gnihton tuB
,retcarahc a gniyalp rotca na sa flesym fo thguoht reven I esuaceb
.aet sih fo pis a sekat dna daeh sih sekahs eH
.sserp sa reh skram taht DI tseug a htiw namow gnuoy mirt a ees ot nrut I   ”?xeR .rM“
.flesym seitrap liatkcoc gnitsoh neeb yltcaxe t’nevah I os
.emit suoicerp ,gniyzzid ,elbidercni siht fo rinevuos A
,thgin taht retal hcuoc eht no rehtegot delruc tis ew sa ttaM llet I ”,ecalp wen a rof gnikool tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’I oS“   * * *   ”.nayR em llaC“
.enecs eht htiw no og dna enil eht egnahc eW   .won litnu
,oediv eht pots I
.snoryhc swen VT dna senildaeh ni maerd I ,thgin tahT
”.seikooc laemtao su edam eitaK tuB
”.eno gnuoy yrev a ekil eroM“
tsuj ti ,dias I ekil ,lleW“
* * *   ”.won ylenol ton m’I“   .sdrow ruof ni
,gnos a steg ydobyrevE
.aremac eht ta gnikool ,neercs taht no ereht ,xeR ykciR s’tahT .tes eht no
,seye eulb-eci reh ni raef on s’ereht dna
”?dnim ni evah uoy od tahW“
”.wohs eht hctaw ot won hguone gib tsomla s’ohw wehpen a dna
boj a ot eerga uoy d’yhW .bulC .C.B ehT
.ni gniredluohs semoc tbuod yreve woN
”—og rehtar d’uoy fI“
yllacitcarp ehs ,su fo htob rof aet tnim kcab gnirb I nehW
?esle enoyreve t’nac yhw nehT
,gnisop ,gnilimS
.teknalb reh ni depparw pu ekaw I esuaceb
,laid eht no swalc ym tser I
,wohs eht fo doog eht rof ro
...si ,repapswen erom fo sllab delpmurc rednu ,edisnI
.mih rof yppah m’I taht dna
,eybdoog evaw ew dna
.rehtegot esac eht ekam ew tub ,enim naht ecneulfni s’ttaM erom s’ti kniht I .eerga yeht
,deneppah ydaerla s’taht gnihtyreve ot derapmoc tub
dna neht pu steg ttaM
.eb dluoc I dehsiw I
.selacs ym revo spitregnif sih gnihsurb
.ylsuoires os reh gnikat rof em gniknaht pots t’ndluoc yehT
,efil ym ni emit tsrif eht rof dna
.xob yrekab eht snepo eH
.em gnieye s’ttaM ,pu kool I nehw dna
.ereht neeb syawla tsuj s’eh ekil s’ti dna
.tuo hserF“   ”?sekac kcor ynA
tey denrael t’ndah I hcum os saw erehT
.tpircs a morf gnidaer tsuj enoemos t’nsaw tahT“
,meht nepo I nehW
rotani-esreveR eht rof tops a gnidnif flesym erutcip I
.dah evah thgim ti rovalf yna tsol
”...erew stnerap reH
,yako s’ti ,yllaer ton ,on
,hcuoc eht ot sdaeh eH
,neht ecnis yad yreve tuB
.efas em peek oT .thgis nialp ni em gnidih fo yaw a sa
.nikpan a gniraew saw I ekil hcum oot dekool ti
”.erofeb od ot no dellac neeb reven
?em si eno hcihw wonk I od woH
* * *   .emit tsrif eht rof ,ti ot olleh yas oT
.etis noitcua na ot og dna bat rehtona pu nepo I neht dna ,ruoh na
,ereh sevil ehs ekil hcuoc eht otno sllaf ehS
.srehto eht dna eitaK tuoba kniht I
.yspoT ,yako s’tahT“
eno yub llits ll’I ebyam rO
.gum eht dnuora flesreh sparw
).sweiver oediv fo ytnelp nees ev’I tub ,letoh a ni neeb yllautca reven ev’I
yldesoppus sah yspoT
em ot dednah s’tahw gnikat neeb ev’I
”?rof gnitiaw ew era tahW“
,gnitseretni s’ti fo lla
,ti fo dne eht yB
”.dnah no dah I repap ylnO“
,ti tuoba niatrec leef dluoc I hsiw tsuj I ”.wonk I“
.ylduorp yas I ”,egatniV“
”retsnom“ drow eht ,sey dnA