.deggag tsomla eH
.sdnah sih htiw deyalp dna deddon dloraH
.nehctik eht fo tuo gnipmots erofeb namow dega-elddim eht dlot eh
syart dna stop fo dnuos ehT
.noitcaer s’yob eht ta gnilims ,dias nniuQ ”,dloraH s’tahT“   ”?eman ruoy s’tahW .noh ,olleh ,lleW“
selbat eht nwod gnipiw ,krow ta drah saw namow redlo eht dna
.tsugsid ni elzzum sih gnilknirw morf peek ot thguof nniuQ
”—eh tub ,yrros m’I“
,nepeed dluoc hsulb s’yob eht kniht t’ndid eH
,gninrub ro ydaer t’nsaw ti gnimrifnoc retfA
,nehctik eht ni kcab ecnO
.but a naht rewohs ni-klaw a fo erom saw ti os
,rof denruter reven dna dniheb tfel sremotsuc staoc fo yltsom detsisnoc tI
.atnegaR ta regnif yrgna na detniop dna
.renroc eht otni delbmarcs ohw dloraH fo thgis eht ta ezorf ehs
roolf eht no ezag sih dexif nniuQ .mih gnihcaorppa
.nesohc ym dnuora gnikcams rof si tahT“
.swap sih htiw ylisae meht pirg dluoc eh os
yrgnuh og enoyna tel reveN
.meht debburcs eh sa ecalp ni slwob dna setalp eht dloh ot drah saw ti dna delbmert swap siH
,eluR snogarD erehW ,seires ysatnaf eht setirw ohw
”.uoy fo htob hsinup ll’I rO“
.ti riaper ,lieN ,retneprac eht evah dluow eh erehw
.enola ti eldnah dluow eh dias dna meht deknaht yletilop eh tub
.pleh eht esu dluoc ew ,yawynA“
.tfel dna slaem rieht rof diap wef A
.mottob dna sedis eht tsniaga ti nettalf ot liat sih gnisu ylluferac
?tsrif pu tel ay naC“
.niap ni dessih llits eh tub
,gnihton dias nniuQ
.rood eht rof dedaeh dna deddon dloraH
”?keew tsal emit drah a uoy evag ohw ekard eht taht t’nsI“
.gnikooc ,htam ,gnidaer
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.ecalp sih ni mih tup I dalg yllaer m’I nehT“   ”.eno eht s’tahT“
.evots eht no top gnimaets eht morf yawa denrut dna dehgis nniuQ
,thgir lla uoy erA“
”.tihs em llet ot elpoep attol a evah t’ndiD“
”?stnerap ruoy ot deneppah tahw oS“
.hgual ot egru eht thguof nniuQ
wonk I“   ”.og taht tel tsuj t’nac I wonk uoy tuB“
.dloraH ot kcab denrut eH ”.struh llits tI“
,tluciffid saw top eht otni gnillif eht gniruoP
eht no doof dehsams eht ta liat sih debbaj eH
.dias esylA ”,uoy ,pots ,hO“
.tnaruatser eht edisni denruter nniuQ
.noh ,llaC s’hcrairtaM a s’tahT“
swap sih rof dengised hsurb burcs laiceps eht debbarg eH
kcen sih dnuora deit hcuop eht ffo dehctans ylkciuq liatnroh ehT
.nehctik eht otni meht deirrac dna
.daeh s’yob eht ni gninrut sleehw eht was eH
.meht fo pot no yllacitcarp saw eh litnu eciton t’ndid yehT
”.ytip rey ref ksa t’nia I“
”,flehs eht no ereht thgir era shtolchsaw dna paoS“   .reisae tol a naelc gnitteg ekam dluohs erusserp retaw artxe ehT
erew ew erofeb uoy ot yas ot detnaw I gnihtemos saw erehT“
”.srennam emos wonk retteb eh
.rorroh ni mih ta derats sremotsuc gnidnuorrus eht dna ehS
llits era dna edistuo peels ohw snogard wonk I
rehto hcae delcric sekard egral ehT
.sdnah reh ni elfir a
.redluohs eht no nniuQ gnippals
.nehctik eht otni kcab mih gnikconk
,wollof ot uoy rof drah elttil a llits si efil nogard wonk I .noh ,pu taht ekam t’ndluow I“   ”.gnikoj er’uoY“
,yob eht rof egral oot deraeppa tesolc eht ni sehtolc eht fo llA
.noitcerid s’nniuQ ni gnikool dediova enoyrevE
.roolf eht ot tuons sih gnihcuot ,niaga dewob eH
.edam dah sekard eht ssem eht pu gninaelc tog neht
.tleb eht otni sehcton wen tuc ylluferac eh
.revo mih dekool nniuQ
.kcab eht morf esion a draeh eh
,tsehc s’yob eht ta pots ot hguone llams erew taht stnap fo riap a dnuof yllautneve eh tub
.raja rood eht tfel tub
daeh reh dnuora gnuh riah nworb reH
.delims nniuQ   ”?trats I od nehW“
,eno siht ezingocer t’ndid eH
”.segelivirp laiceps yna uoy evig t’nseod
.slenitneS reh fo eno eb ot demussa eh ohw saw reh dniheB
.mih dniheb reh gnivom
nellows saw eye eno ,roolf eht no suoicsnoc ylerab liatnroh dnoces eht was dna nwod dekool eH
”?yawyna erac ayddahW“   ”?uoy evah ,elpoep rehto dnuora devil reven ev’uoY“
”.kcab thgir eb ll’I .ereh yatS“
thgin eht rof pu gninaelc hsinif ot dedeen llits yeht taht tuo detniop nniuQ
yob eht sdrawot detlob nniuQ
,seldnah top eht dloh ot sgniw sih fo swalc eht gnisU
.nworb nedlog ylevol a denrut dah tsurc sti dna suoiciled dellems tI
,dloraH ,yakO“   ”.dloraH“   ”?eman ruoy s’tahW .nniuQ m’I“
.no meht peek ot pu stnap eht dloh ot dah eh dna
”,taht ekil uoy otni gninnur rof yrros m’I“
,pu denaelc yllanif saw ssem eht nehW
”,ereh tuo teg retteb uoy
”.ti ot neppah gnihtemos tel t’nac I
.si eh niht woh ees uoY
.gnol oot rof nus eht ni tfel neeb dah taht
.daeh sih ni eloh wen a gnittup fo daetsni
moor eht fo elddim eht raen selbat eht fo eno ta gnittiS
.ezis sih enoemos rof t’nerew yeht suoivbo llits saw ti tub
”.sehtolc ruoy uoy gnignirb tsuj m’I ,xaleR“
.gniklat enod er’uoY .on ,oN“   ”—tub ,taht
I tahw saw taht fi daed eb ydaerla dluow uoy
.yob eht ot enod neeb dah egamad suoires yna taht raeppa t’ndid ti tub
nehctik eht otni kcab dedaeh eH
ylsuovren rehto hcae ta dekool snogard dna snamuh gniniamer ehT
.taht tuoba yrroS“
”.deen ni esoht depleh syawla apap yM .tibah fo ecroF“
.renroc eht ni flehs eht ta gnitniop ,dias nniuQ
.htuom ruoy hctaw uoY“
.elbat elgnis a no meht gnilip dna sehsid gniniamer eht gnirehtag detrats nniuQ
.ecnelis gnol rehtonA
.nehctik eht ot denruter eh
”?fo erac ekat ot deen ew od sredro rehto tahW
.snisuoc revlis sih sa ssenildaed emas eht evah t’ndid liat sih
yawrood eht ni doots namuh ehT
resserd eht morf xob llams a debbarg ehS
,nehctik eht otni deklaw esylA
.pu dehsaw teg nac uoy tub ,uoy rof gib elttil a s’tI .sriatspu buthtab a evah I ,no emoC
.eerf semoc nittuN .’nipleH“   ”?tahw fo tuO“
,roolf eht ot eno dekconk eh ,eciwT
”.pan a rof tnemesab ym otni ekorb uoy ecnis og ot ecalp on evah uoy gnimussa m’I
.moorhtab eht ot denruter eH
”?taht od ay d’yhW
”,doof ym gnitae erofeb taht fo thguoht ev’dluohs uoy ebyam ,lleW“   ”.ti ’niyub t’nia llitS“   ”.flesym
.nehctik eht tfel dna deddon esylA
.pu dekool neht tnemom a rof sehtolc sih ta derats dloraH
,yob eht erongi ll’I
.tnaruatser eht gnisol ton er’uoY“
swaj sih ni liat s’nogard eht koot dna dehgis nniuQ   .ylesuforp gnideelb ecaf dna
”.aera siht revo selur ohw nogard eht ,wonk uoY
.dab leef uoy ekam ot gniyrt ton m’I“
”?won sneppah tahw ,oS“
”,taht wonk t’nod uoY“
.aera gninid egral eht otni kcab deirruh eH
.erom rof sriatsnwod aera egarots eht otni daeh ot decrof saw eh os puc eno rof hguone dah ylno
.yob eht rof lwob a otni wets eht fo tsal eht deruop nniuQ
,eta namuh eht sA
.tsehc sih debbur dna pu tas ylwols yob ehT
.nesohc s’hcrairtaM eht kcatta tsuj t’nac uoy ,oS“   ”?oS“
.eralg yci na htiw yob eht no delrihw esylA   .delbmurg dloraH ”,yrt nac hctiB“
”,nwod denrut gnieb tuoba rettib llits s’ehs kniht I“
.deilper dloraH erofeb ecnelis feirb a saw erehT   .deksa nniuQ
.rorroh ni pu daeh sih dehctans nniuQ .detuohs dloraH
,esaelP“   .ecaf nekcirts-cinap sih fo sedis eht ot gnulc riah nworb ,ysaerG
”!dooF .etsaW .t’noD .uoY“
”.dnif dluoc I tseb eht saw tI
.sredro ’sremotsuc eht ot dnet ot deunitnoc esylA ,dekrow eh sA
.ti enod evah d’I ,uoy truh ot detnaw I fI“   .deirc yob eht
”.ti dekil yeht dalG“ .delims nniuQ
”.uoy no ecin kool sehtolc esohT“
.der denrut yletaidemmi skeehc sih dna
swap s’nogard a htiw krow retteb ot srevel ssarb egral htiw esu nogard rof dezimotsuc neeb dah rewohs ehT
.retnuoc eht no ti tas dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,moor eht fo elddim eht ni doots esylA
,laineg detserc-neerg a sA
.taorht sih otni depael traeh s’nniuQ   ”!klat ot deen eW“
.thgir er’uoy epoh I“
.tnaruatser ym ni yrgnuh seog eno on tub
elbidua ylerab edisni snioc eht fo dnuos eht
,yks thgin eht fo mih dednimer selacs kcalb reH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.nwod ecalp eht nrub ot gnimoc si atnegaR naem I“
htaerb sih rednu erows eH
.esor worb s’dloraH
,elap sih morf gnileep maercs sseldnuos a dna
riahc ybraen eht no sresuort dna trihs eht decalp nniuQ
.ylbatirri dias nniuQ
”.reh ot klat og uoy elihw sruoh wef a rof ecalp eht retfa kool nac I ,tnaw uoy fI
.htuom sih otni slufnoops delevohs eh sa ti ni ecaf sih deirub ylraen namuh ehT
:tol a em thguat apap yM .enif s’tI“   ”.yrroS“
.netsil t’ndluow eh tub ,ti no gnikrow ereh kcab erew uoy mih llet ot deirt I
.em deppals ehs ekil mih pals atnegaR ro taht rehtie saw tI“
”.em ot klat uoy nehw em ta kool dnA“
”,noh ,taht enod ev’t’ndluohs uoY“
,yhtlif os erew sehtolc s’yob ehT
”,mih ton m’I ,lleW“
”.yadot nesohc ym dekcatta uoY“
,yart a no meht decalp ,slwob otni wets emos deruop eh os
.ylteews gnilims ,deksa atnegaR
”!?era ay kniht ay od ohW“
,roolf eht no ti deppord dna
.eip eht dehsinif eh sa flesmih ot gnimmuh
.moordeb desunu eht ot llah eht nwod gniog dna rood eht gnisolc erofeb ylper a rof tiaw t’ndid eH
,selbat fo riap a otni dereggats eH
”.won ,slaem ruoy ot kcab teg nac uoY“ .dias esylA
.stseug eht ot tuo ti deirrac neht dna
”.xes rof srovaf edart t’nod I dnA“
,pu naelc pleh ot dereffo neve sremotsuc lareveS
”.ecalp siht gnisol
.liat sih htiw ekard denwod eht gnikirts llits derednuht nniuQ
.si ti sa deffats-trohs er’ew tub ,taht etaicerppa I“
rorroh ni gninediw seye eulb-yci
,walc elgnis a gnisu dna talf tleb eht gniyaL
”.deirrow tog I os ,teiuq saw ti dna elihw a rof enog neeb ev’uoy ,lleW“
”.em tae at deirt ’pleh‘ at detnaw ohw gred tsal eht ’nA“
.der was eh ,mih dnuora doof detsaw enoemos revenehw tuB
”?aera gninid eht ni esylA pleh og uoy t’nod yhW“ .dias nniuQ
.yart a no meht gninil dna slwob rellams otni wets gniruop nageb eh sa tnemom a rof eman eht no derednop nniuQ ”…kraT“   ”.netsil
,deksa yeht nehw knird a rof stseug eht nioj dluoc eh dehsiw nniuQ
,noitidnoc sih gniredisnoc tub hcrairtaM eht fo draeh t’ndah yob eht eveileb ot drah ti dnuof nniuQ
”?ffuts fo dnik taht od sgreD“
.deretne eh nehw nniuQ ta deralg eH
.ti fo ffo seye sih ekat t’ndluoc osla eh tub
,dehsinomda esylA
.ylkciuq dias nniuQ
daem fo ksac tsal ehT
”.enod er’uoy nehw uoy rof gnitiaw naelc gnihtemos evah ll’I
,yeH“   ”.fo demaerd apap ym ecalp eht tog yllanif I
”.noitseuq ym rewsna woN .detnaw
”.ezis ruoy ni gnihtyna dnif ot drah s’ti os ,llew oot gnitae neeb t’nevah uoY“
”.hcuot t’nod uoy ,hcrairtaM eht ot gnignoleb gnihtyna taht si rebmemer ot elur doog a tub
.aera gninid eht otni ylisae deirrac gnillaf
.sselemoh og dik eht tel evah dluow reven ehs
.ti enod reven dah eh dehsiw eH
,tfel ydaerla dah sremotsuc ehT
”.em retfa ’nikool enoemos saw ereht ,haey neht ,tuo em tup dluoc yeht litnu ssa ym tiw pu tup naem ay fI“
.gniremmis saw wets eht erehw evots eht no top rehto eht ot noitnetta sih denrut eh
seye wolley reh saw ecnereffid ylno ehT
.rood eht fo tuo gniyrruh sih revo
”.taht ekil reh ot gnihtyreve dellips tsuj I eveileb t’nac I“
.taht swonk enoyrevE
.wap reh htiw elzzum eht ssorca drah mih kcurts erofeb denruter elims elbaima reH
.doolb detsat eh tub ,ereht llits erew yehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.hcnip a ni sgar doog edam yeht tub
,taes reh morf esor dna dehgis ehS
”.si ehs ohw swonk enoyrevE
,latrop eht dehcaer eh ecnO
egabrag fo mih dednimer taht gnihtemos fo ffihw a thguac eh ,resolc tog eh sa tub
.llah eht nwod morf gnimoc spetstoof draeh eh nehw
”.dnim ni taht peek ll’I“
.esnopser ni deddon esylA
.sehtolc sih ta nwod dekool dloraH sa did ti wohemos tub
tnew eh sa llah eht otni roolf eht no sehtolc yhtlif eht gnikcik ,tfel neht eH
niaga esion eht draeh eH
.nrot yldab saw dna
ybab a erew uoy nehw uoy retfa dekool ev’tsum enoemoS“   ”.yna dah reveN“
.gniwollaws erofeb htuom sih desolc yob eht fi llet t’ndluoc nniuQ
,daeh sih koohs ylkciuq yob ehT
:uoy dlot ydaerla I“
”.esoht attuo egnahc dnA
.ecnaifed sti deunitnoc ydob sih sa deifirroh saw eH
”.ssa na si kraT swonk enoyrevE
.nehctik eht ot denruter yeht os
.knird dna doof fo ssem eht pu naelc ot gar a desu eh ,txeN
.snroh devruc fo riap elbuod eht gnidulcni
.nniuQ no tsol t’nsaw tcejbus ni egnahc ehT
,revo dekconk neeb dah taht selbat eht dethgir eH
,ressapsert a eb thgim uoY“
.mrof ynobe reh ot sknaht erom neve tuo doots hcihw
.wap elgnis a htiw roolf eht ot redurtni eht dennip nniuQ   .spil yrd
,ycavirp sih tuoba dloraH morf tsrubtuo yrgna rehtona gniticile
”.wodniw eht hguorht deppilS
.norpa reh fo meh eht htiw gniyalp
,nehctik eht deretne yeht nehW
”.uoy pleh dna ecin eb ot gniyrt tsuj m’I
.peels at ecalp a ref ’nikool tsuJ“
”.nesohc s’atnegaR s’eH
,mih dnuora nellaf dah stop lareveS
.ti fo erac ekat ll’I ,thgir llA“
.oot ,yadretsey togrof uoy taht llems nac I“
”?kaeps dluoc uoy yas I diD“   ”—atnegaR“
,taht ekil gniklat uoy draeh slenitnes reh fo eno ro ehs fI
semit lareves dedlof erew seveels ehT
.deddon ylwols eH
.ti derrits dna noops egral eht koot eh
.deniur t’nsaw wets eht os evots eht morf devom neeb dah top ehT
.kcalb erew slianregnif sih dna trid htiw degdums saw ydob sih fo trap desopxe yrevE
”?em rof aera gninid eht no eye na peek uoy naC
”?uoy rof skrow yob tahT“
”.esuops s’esle enoemos gnittih sa ti fo knihT
,pot eht revo hguod fo eceip lanif eht decalp eh ,yltsaL
.ecalp ni delbmert dna raef sih edih regnol on dluoc eH
.roolf eht no kcilc t’ndid swalc sih os ylwols devom dna wol dehcuorc eH
.peels ot ecalp a tsuj naht erom detnaw uoy ekil sdnuoS“ .delkcuhc nniuQ
.sriahc gnidnuorrus eht dna meht gnirettacs
,daeh sih desiar dna detrons neht eH
,repmet a tog s’atnegaR ,woN .noh ,wonk I“
.mih dniheb morf dias esylA
,ti ni sehcton artxe emos deen dluow taht tleb a
.uoy rof tuo ti lleps ll’I os ,dnatsrednu ot uoy rof drah era swal nogard wonk I“
.liat sih htiw nihc eht no ekard rehto eht gnikirts ,nups nniuQ nehT
,ylkciuq os eta eH
.reklatsthgiN egral a saw
”.daed uoy detnaw I fi won yb uoy dellik ev’dluow I taht uoy gnillet fo derit gnitteg m’I dnA“
.hteet sih ssorca eugnot sih nar dna doots ylwols eH
”?won tuo uoy kcik I rehtar d’uoy sselnU
”.uoy naht ytrid ssel
.od ot krow hcum oot saw ereht tub
.gninraw ro noitatiseh tuohtiw mih fo tuo deruop sdrow ehT
”?drah taht mih otni nur ot evah uoy diD“
,ytiP .wonk t’nod I“
”.sesiurb wef a htiw uoy evael naht esrow od ll’yeht
”!?gniod ay er’tahW !aohW“
”.uoy ot ti deef lliw ehs eugnot ruoy dloh t’nod uoy fI
,meht rof esu on dah nniuQ
”.re‘ wonk t’noD .hO“
,eiskooB ,yrruFoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.aera eht fo hcrairtaM eht ,atnegaR saw tI
.dloraH ot dias nniuQ ”,detpurretni
.yob eht ta redluohs sih revo decnalg dna deppots nniuQ   ”?taht ekil tsuJ“
,tae dluoc snogard dna snamuh erehw tnaruatser a detnaw syawla eH
.ehs sa emas ,reklatsthgiN a saw ti tub
.doog ytterp tuc tog llits uoy ,lleW“
”?uoy rof od I nac tahw ,hcrairtaM yM“
”.rehtien pleh rey deen t’noD“ .delbmurg dloraH
.meht gniwollof yob eht dnif ot desirprus saw eH
swaperof egral sih neewteb htorb dna ,selbategev
nniuQ gnigadnab dehsinif esylA
.noh ,t’ndluohs uoY“
.lufniap naht gnisirprus erom saw tI
.rewol daeh sih deppord nniuQ
.livnA dlroW dna ,trAtnaiveD
”.sriatspu wets emos tog I ,no emoC .xif hguone ysae na s’taht tuB
”.ecalp rey atni ekorb I ’nA
,taem eht htiw dellif top egral eht debbarg ylluferac neht eH
.won retteb tif dluohs ti tub ,edargpu tsetaen eht t’nsaw tI
.niaga delkcuhc eH
”.’ninrom siht hsaw at togref tsuJ“
.nehctik eht sdrawot esylA wollof ot doots eh sa denaorg eH .dias nniuQ
tser ot ecalp a dedeen ehs tneve eht ni esylA rof edisa tes neeb dah moor desunu ehT
.ffo doolb eht hsaw ot evah neht dna ,ydob eht fo esopsid ,ti llik ot evah ot doom eht ni t’nsaw osla eh tuB
,yawa lwob eht devohs dna mih ta deralg dloraH
”.mih pleh ot tnaw I dna ,mih retfa kool ot eno on sah eH“
.decseiuqca nniuQ   ”.ehtaerb t’naC
.llew ytterP“   ”?od ew d’woH
”.ereh boj a gnivah dnim t’ndluow uoy gnipoh m’I
.ti rettahs dluow enola thgiew sih fi sa tlef nniuQ
.ti naelc dluoc eh os retnuoc eht no top egral eht dial dna
.deffatsrednu erew yeht ecnis netfo saw hcihw
.naelc gnitteg denoitnem nniuQ nehw seye sih ni feiler eht gniyned on saw ereht tuB
.ecnelis ni derats dloraH   ”.moor eht evah I
,atnegaR gniwonk ,oslA
”.gnuoy saw I nehw ni em koot apap ym tub ,stnerap ym ot deneppah tahw rebmemer t’nod I
”,nrub t’nseod ti erus ekam dna ,taht hctaW“
,nniuQ“   .eson sih dellif
”?ereh gniod uoy era tahw dna uoy era ohW
nettogrof ylgnimees neeb dah reilrae morf thgif ehT
,uoy truh ot tnaw t’nod I
.deen I gniht tsal eht si sihT“
.aera gninid niam eht morf sehsid fo gnirettalc eht dna hsarc duol a emac erehT
,egnar gnikirts fo tuo tsuj saw nniuQ ecnO
”—gnihtyreve si ,nniuQ ,yeH“
.hturt eht llet uoy ekam saw did ehs lla ykcul er’uoY
.sehsid eht ot kcab denrut eH
”.em kcuf at deirt taht dias ohw nam tsaL“ .denworf dloraH
,ekarD navE yb ”elaT s’nogarD A“
.rettahs t’ndid yeht os tsom naht reidruts edam erew sehsid eht ,yllufknaht tub
sgum eht tuo gnihsaw saw eH
esab ediw a htiw dengised yllaiceps erew slisnetu ehT
.selacs rieht hsaw retteb ot daeh rewohs laiceps a dna
.tsurc eip eht otni
.kcehc ni regna sih gnidloh ,deilper nniuQ
,drow a tuohtiW .deb eht no
”.on yas ot eerf er’uoY
”,oot ,gnola emoc uoy ,yawynA“
.ecnatsid rieht gnipeek
.doohtluda gnihcaorppa tsuj saw namuh eht
.secaf gninnirg dna rethgual laivoj htiw dellif saw aera gninid eht sa
.noitcepsni rof nrut s’dloraH emac ti dna
.reh ot denrut dna deppots eH
,ydaer t’nsaw eip ehT
”.ti naelc ot deen annog er’ew ,noh ,no emoC .gnol taht tsal t’nseod llaC eht ,thgir rebmemer I fI“
,dnim sih ni ekops eciov ehT
,detcepxe nniuQ naht retteb mih tif sehtolc ehT
”.neppah ti ees ot ecnahc eht dah reven eh tub
niaga dehcnilf eH
.tnerapsnart ylraen saw eh elap os dekool eh dna
”!?ecalp siht ni evah I elur eno eht si tahW“
.detseuqer saw taht ela fo spuc eht ruop ot
.tleb eht tpek tub
?em ot taht seod ehs fi tahW“
.rethgual htiw deraor nniuQ   ”!?tahW“
,tnemtnio lanicidem dna segadnab emos ,stnetnoc sti deitpme
.rood eht sdrawot mih deggard dna
.sehtolc dlo rof moor egarots eht emoceb osla dah tI
”,htab a deen t’noD“
.daeh sih gnuh nniuQ
”?drah os taht saW“
,ereh kcab emoc I nehw tub
”.elbanosaernu ton s’ehs tub
.edis s’nniuQ ot deirruh esylA
.ereh peels nac uoy dna uoy yap ll’I
.dnuora denrut dna deppots eh
.sriatspu nniuQ dewollof dna
.tuo uoy depleh I esuaceb tsuj em rof krow ot uoy tcepxe t’nod I
.meht no sehsid dah llits lareves tub
trid htiw degdums saw ecaf s’yob ehT
,gnivom deppots dah redurtni ehT
”,eeyolpme tsewen ym evigrof esaelP“
.strats drah ni emac shtaerb reh dna
?nwo ruoy no pu gnisolc yako uoy erA“
”.ti tae uoy ekam I erofeB“ .roolf
.rood eht rof dedaeh dna nups atnegaR
”?taht od eh dluow yhW“
?atnegaR tuoba tahW .tcejbus eroS .thgir llA“
,stsirw sih dnoyeb dehcaer llits dna
.daeh sih detlit nniuQ
”!ereh ni llits m’I“ .deirc dloraH
.em ot dluow ehs naht uoy ot esrow od dluow ehs wenk I esuaceB“
”.yats ot ecalp a uoy nevig ev’dluow ehs tub
”elaT s’nogarD A“ saw sihT
”.nwo reh no esle gnihtyreve eganam ot sah esylA roop os nehctik eht ni emit ym fo tsom dneps I
.gnilnogard dehctah ylwen a ekil gnikahs
”.namuh a saw apap ym ,oN ?huH“
denimreted eb t’ndluoc roloc lanigiro eht
,tops eht ot detoor deniamer liatnroh rehto ehT
”.hturt eht em lleT“   ”--syad owt mih derih tsuj I
.detuohs eciov A ”!nniuQ“
”.peep a edam reven dna esrow raf nekat ev’uoY“
.llah eht ot nehctik eht fo edis rehto eht no rood rehtona hguorht nniuQ dewollof eh sa htaerb sih rednu delbmurg yob ehT   ”.em wollof woN
.nevo eht ni eip eht no dekcehc eH
,meht dnuora gnir-imes a demrof dah sremotsuc rehto eht dna revo deppilf neeb dah selbat eht fo eno ,ydaerlA
.moordeb eraps eht ot llah kcab eht otni esylA dewollof dloraH dna nniuQ   ”.gnihtyna
”,revo s’wohs ,enoyreve ,thgi’A“
.gnileer nogard revlis eht gnidnes ,ekard tsrif eht otni redluohs sih demmals eh ,tsriF
.wets eht fo llems eht derewoprevo hcnets sih nehT
.yawa ti sevig ecnaraeppa er’uoY“
.tuo hsaw t’ndluow dna deregnil raef fo niats eht tub ,sehsid eht dehsaw eh sa yawa sthguoht eht hsup ot deirt eH
.hcrairtaM ehT“   ”?ohW“
.egamad erom od dluoc yeht erofeb sekard owt eht dehcaorppa nniuQ
.neht reh htiw laed ll’I os ,retal ro renoos yb emoc ll’ehS
,sehtolc eht fo tser eht htiw tleb eht tfel eH
,rood eht tuo deraeppasid ehs ecnO
”.tey ereh dnuora krow sgniht woh wonk t’nseod dna ereh wen s’eH“
moor kcab eht otni ti deggard eH
,liat sih htiw egdun eltneg a esylA evag dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
pu naelc esylA gnipleh hsiniF .won thgiR“
”.gninetsil ton er’yeht tub ,pu ti kaerb ot deirt I
”.hctarcs morf dliuber ot evah annog m’I
.dnuora nrut t’ndid tub dehgis nniuQ
.seenk sih ot hcaer ylno dluohs taht trihs a dna
”?ecalp s’ylimaf rey siht ,oS“
.sdoow eht ni gnivil ylekil saw eh
”,tuo teg neht ssem eht dna doof ruoy rof yaP“
.pu denaelc teg dna rood eht yb sehtolc ruoy evaeL“
.raey fo emit siht dnuora dekcap ytterp steg ecalp sihT .haeY“   ”?boj A“
,esac eht s’taht fI“
.ylgninetaerht dias nniuQ
ylduol delworg hcamots s’yob ehT
”?noh ,naem uoy od tahW“
”,tae ot ereh ton m’I tub ,nniuQ ,yrroS“
.maerd s’apap ym saw ecalp sihT
.ees I ,krow ta drah er’uoY“
”.yadot mih tem tsuj I .ereh krow t’nseod eH“
”.emit gnol a ni ekam I eno tsal eht eb thgim ti dab ooT“ .dedaf elims siH
.desolc elzzum sih deppans nniuQ   ”.netsil uoy woN
.top eht gnirrits nageb dna
.namuh a yb ’detpoda‘ saw I“
”,yrros eb dluohs uoY“
.dedda nniuQ ”,dias ehs tahW“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ekarD navE yb
,ni nrut dluoc yeht erofeb
.yawrood eht ni deraeppa noos dloraH
:raelc s’ti os tsuJ
,mih otni demmals dna
”?nug a evah uoy od yhW“
.swap rieht rednu thguac knird dna doof eht ot suoivilbo yletelpmoc erew yehT
”—si dneirf rey ’niwonk mih hsinup annog aY“
.tcejbo t’ndid yob eht ,esirprus s’nniuQ oT
.yrujni sih ot dnet dluoc ehs os reh fo tnorf ni nwod tas nniuQ
.roolf eht ffo pu flesmih gnikcip tsuj saw dloraH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,sesiurb wef a naht rehtO
”.elpoep kcatta snogard ekam seno reitsan eht fo emos draeh I
”.em llik ot ’niog erew ay thguohT“
”.pu taht gnignirb eb ot emit tseb eht yllaer toN“
.ydaer s’ti nehw eip eht dna wets eht fo slwob owt deen I“
.mih deksa reven I .tliug ,ssendnik
.tar a tsuj saw ti depoh dna
,ksa ot gnitae dehsinif dah yob eht litnu detiaw nniuQ
,evissergga…tib a s’ehs ,eruS
.yob eht tespu dah eh gniwonk
”.ereh saw I emit tsal mih gniees rebmemer t’nod I
secips dna sbreh eht fo tnecs eht sa depacse hgis detnetnoc A
,ecaf sih dnuora mrots a ni gniylf riah ysaerg
.tnaruatser ym ni doof etsaw t’nod uoY“
.gnihtyna tnaw t’nod I“
.uoy no drah oot eb t’now ehs erus m’I
.gniht doog a saw ti detcepsus nniuQ
.mrof depurdauq sih fo esu ekam ot woh mih thguat dah ecitcarp fo sraey tub
.nekorb neeb dah meht fo eno tub
ssa sih no ekard eht dekconk ylno wolb eht sa
.kcis elpoep gnitteg uoy evah t’now I
,esylA ot snioc fo hcuop eht evag ,dehgis nniuQ
.ekard eht morf yawa mih gnihsup nageb ehS
.ffo tuc ylkciuq saw tub htuom sih denepo dloraH
.deilper atnegaR
:selur owt dah ylno apap ym ,yawynA
”?siht attuo teg ayddahw ’nA“ .nworf lacitpeks a gniraew
.ereht tuo noitamrofni fo secruos ynam eb t’ndluow erehT
”?yawyna tuoba gnithgif yeht erew tahW
.kcen sih rof dehcaer ylsuovren eh sa
.detlusni gnieb ekil t’nod s'hcrairtaM tub ,riaf s’ehS“
.dloraH ot kcab denrut neht eH
.em ref gred taht ot deil ay ,ereht kcaB“
.trihs yttar s’yob eht ot detniop eH
?yllaeR“   ”.seod eh ,seY“
”?yob eht rof ytilibisnopser ekat uoy oS“
denediw seye s’dloraH
tuoba retteb leef em ekam t’nseod tahT“
,dloraH ,tahw uoy lleT“
noops eht pu dekcip eH
.redro eht tuo llif ot gniog erofeb sehsid eht gnihsaw dehsinif nniuQ
.ylmrif dias esylA
”?evaheb ot nesohc reh llet ehs t’nseod yhw
,uoy gnipleh rof nruter ni
”.tih gib a saw eip taem ruoy tub ,tey detnuoc t’nevah I
”.oga raey a saw tI“
.dnuora delrihw nniuQ
”.segdurg dloh ot ekil snogard ,lleW“
.reh decrovid dnabsuh tsal reh retfa gnihtolc fo tol a ffo deppord osla esylA tub
”.ereh eb t’ndluow uoy ro
”.pu denaelc mih teg dna kcab eht ni mih ekat ot tnaw I
.ssem a gnikam ereh tuo stoidi owt er’erehT“
”.niaga ereh ni kaerb reven ll’uoy esimorp ot uoy tnaw I
swaj sih ni yart eht debbarg eH
”.thgir desiar neeb t’nsah taht gnilhctah a ekil stca eH .wonk I“
,norpa reh htiw ecaf sih fo edis eht ta debbad yltneg ehS ”.llits dloH
.retnuoc eht ot delddaw dna
.nwod tuhs dloraH erofeb gniog noitasrevnoc eht peek ot dediced eH
,detcepxe sa tsuJ
”.taht erofeb keew eht dnA
,tuo ekard eht gnissot dna nepo rood eht gnikcik retfA
.flesym deef nac I taht ees nac uoy dnA“
.doots nniuQ erehw ot moor eht dessorc ehS
”elaT s’nogarD A“   yojne esaelP
.ecaf sih fo trap rehtona dehcuot ehs nehw niaga dessih eH
.ria eht ni sliat dekips rieht gnivaw dna
.nehctik ym ni eb ot gniog er’uoy fi eno gnitteg er’uoY“
.esnopser ni detrons dloraH   .dias nniuQ
.wol dewob dna esylA ot txen doots nniuQ
”.doof etsaw t’nod dna
.nib hsaw eht ot revo deklaw dna
tnedor a naht regral hcum dednuos tI .deneffits dna
,nesohc ym emoceb ot dereffo erew uoy esuaceb tsuJ
.niaga eip eht no dekcehc dna pu tog nniuQ
?reh tuoba wonk ton uoy od woH“
”!em truh t’nod-d esaelp
.mih erofeb doof rieht gnitteg saw enoemos taht deyonna saw kraT“
,uoy otni gninnur em tuoba rettib oot ton er’uoy fI“
”.ereh dloraH ot gniklat tsuJ .enif m’I“
.wen s’eh ,dias I ekiL“
kcab sih no sehsid fo elip eht decnalab ylluferac eh sa gnihton dias nniuQ
”.nwod denrub erots sih dah ffo reh dessip ohw renwo pohs tsal ehT
.reh ot kcab denrut dna nibhsaw eht otni lwob eht dessot eH
”.nuh ,sksac erom emos redro ot deen ew em sdnimer hcihw ela fo spuc erom eerht rof redro na tog ew dnA
.enif saw yob eht
.nosmirc peed dehsulf ecaf s’dloraH
.no egadnab eht tup ehs sa
nogard a rof dettifer neeb dah moorhtab ehT
gnisselb a saw ti desoppus eh ,esac siht nI
.redluohs reh revo kool tsal eno tohs ehS
.gnihtyna kaerb t’ndid nniuQ erus ekam ot deen I“ .dias esylA
”—fi dnim t’ndluow I
,noitcepsni resolc nopU
”.pleh eht esu dluoc ay derugiF“
stnetnoc eht ytpme tlit ylluferac ot swap sih desu eh
.deirc esylA ”!potS !nniuQ“
deb fo tuo nettog tsuj dah ehs fi sa
”.swalc reh esu neve t’ndid ehS .enif m’I“   ”?noh
”.me‘ ni ’nimmiws m’I ekil sleeF“ .detrons dloraH
.yawrood eht hguorht ecaf dehsulf ,dnuor reh gnikop ,dias esylA
,yart eht ni hguod eht denil eh sa delims nniuQ  ekarD navE yb
,trons yrgna na htiW
,nib hsaw eht ni sehsid desu eht gnippord dna nevo eht ni eip eht gnicalp retfA
,liarf os tlef ydob s’namuh ehT
.esylA pleh ot llah eht nwod dedaeh neht dna
htaerb sih rednu erows eH
.gniugra erew sliatnroh revlis owt
.dlihc a sesserdda tnerap a sa ytirohtua htiw osla tub
.edis sti ot gnignilc htorb fo stib htiw lwob ytpme eht ot kcab gnittilf tpek seye sih dna sdnah sih htiw deyalp dloraH
,daeh sih desiar edis rehto eht no namuh ehT
”.ffo daeh sih ekat d’ehS
.tleb eht detcepsni nniuQ   .taps yob eht
.selbat rieht ot kcab gniog ylwols erofeb
,sriats eht fo mottob eht dehcaer eh tnemom ehT
”,on yas t’now yletinifed I ,lleW“
.gnireviuq liat sih ,dewollaws nniuQ
.enod eb ot dah ti tub
”.thgin eht rof enod eb ll’uoy dna
,em gnitsurt detrats uoy fi ,lleW“
.sksac eht revo depael eh
”.deid apap ym retfa litnu tliub t’nsaw tI .oN“
eltneg dna gnihtoos
.sksac ela eht raen kcab eht morf gnimoc eb ot demees dna