.atnegaR detroppus reven I ,raelc eb ot dnA
”.suoregnad eb dluoc hcum oot gniklaT .yob ,luferaC“
.gninedrah ezag reh ,liat reh htiw dnuorg eht deppals ehS   ".edis
.seilppus emos gniyub trats dna tuo og annog er'ew ,worromoT
.elbat eht no srepap fo eldnub a revo gniog ,moor gnivil eht ni gnittis dloraH dna esylA dnuof eh ,esuoh eht ot denruter eh nehW
.roolf dna sllaw eht ni edam neeb dah seloh lareveS .lautir gniyerp
dna rehtegot elpoep gnirb ot desoppus saw tnaruatser ehT .detnaw eh maerd eht t'nsaw tI
.edis ruoy no em teg dna
.renroc eht ni esproc eht ta dekool ehS
”.nwod ti evil reven ll'I
enola em evael snogard eht nosaer ylno eht si atnegaR fI
.deretne eh ecno yaw sih dekool dna gniklat deppots yehT
”,noh ,ni flesruoy dnif ot elkcip a ylniatrec s’taht ,lleW“
,eluR snogarD erehW
drawrof deppets ehS
.reh ediseb tas dna resolc devom eH
”.taht naem t’nod uoY“
.elbissop eb dluohs naht htlif erom ni derevoc namuh a fo kcits a saw dloraH
,esle enoyreve ekil enil ni tiaw uoy
.eciohc sih edam ydaerla dah eh gnitacidni dewohs reven
.etacitsemod a ot pu-rennur s’eH
.kcatta txen reh ot tcaer ot dennuts oot eb llits dluow eh
.wam sih morf erif fo emulp a delahxe kraT ,troffe na htiW
.ysaenu mih edam taht nirg gniwonk-lla na delims ehS
.renroc eht ni noihsuc eht no nwod tas nniuQ
.desuac dah kraT egamad eht gniriaper no yletaidemmi krow ot tog dna drow reh ot eurt saw atnegaR
.swap sih no daeh sih detser dna denaorg eH
htiw gnitoof lauqe no uoy tup t’nseod slaem wef a ekam uoy esuaceb tsuJ“
.ydaerla gnidliub eht fo tsom demusnoc dah ezalb ehT
.ezis sih htiw neve ylisae mih demlehwrevo regnad eht eelf ot gnihsur elpoep etarepsed fo aes ehT .epacse ot
.enil ni llaf ot snamuh eht deen tsuj I .reh egnellahc ot edis ym no snogard hguone evah ydaerla I
t’nsaw eh ,koot ti tahw rettam oN .scitilop fo tuo gniyats tuoba dias eh tahw tnaem eH
",siht eldnah ll'I .rehtob t'noD“
.nniuQ“   ”.esilaS em llaC
yawyna skcol tsom etarepo t'ndluoc yehT
.remotsuc gnirrucer a saw ehs tub ,llacer t’ndluoc eh eman s’elacsmaR ehT .hcrairtaM eht fo nesohc eht ,kraT saw tI .liat-
.retteb wenk eh tub ,erif eht rof stekcub barg ot detuohs snamuH
.eciov eht fo noitcerid eht ni dedaeh dna ekard eht morf yawa denrut nniuQ   ”?uoy era erehw ,nniuQ“ .dellac esylA ”!nniuQ“   .esle gnihtyreve tuo denword
.dworc eht evoba daeh sih dloh ot gnilggurts
.namuh eht fo tnorf ni deppets nniuQ   .nageb dloraH
.ereh enoyna llik ot ton gniyrt m'I tub ,troppus ruoy deen t'nod I ,kooL .yrros saw I dias I dnA
,detsetorp dloraH .enola tnew eh
.dleihs a sa ydob sih gnisu
.detuohs dloraH ”!gred
.yats ot ecalp wen a gnidnif eb ot dah ssenisub fo redro tsrif ehT
dias gnihtyna reffo ot droffa t’ndluoc enoyreve dnA
.tnaruatser eht dliuber ot nioc gnitanod dna tuo erew uoy elihw yb gnimoc neeb ev’elpoeP“
stnirpeulb nward-llew s’esylA revo tnew nniuQ ,emit eht ssap oT
.mih htaeneb dehsarht elamef ehT
.atnegaR kcip ot diputs era uoy fi nevE .tsael ta ytsenoh dna yrevarb ruoy tcepser I tub ,em tcejer ot ereh emoc ot deen t’ndid uoY
.uoy rof hcum erac t’ndid ohw snogard eht neve tnaruatser taht devol enoyrevE
.enod neeb dah egamad suoires emos wenk nniuQ ,gnihtaerb deggar sih morf dna pu teg ot wols saw liaT-nroH ehT
”.htiw laed ot kraT llits s’ereht ,atnegaR troppus I fi neve tuB“   ”.noh ,yrros m’I“
".reffo emas eht uoy ekam ot detpmet tsomla m'I
.erehwyna riah nworb yssem taht ezingocer dluoc eH
.eralg gnihtacs a namuh eht tohs ehS
.ti ot semoc ti fi lliw I tub ,ot tnaw I od ron ot nalp t’nod I“
.rettam eht ni yas a evah t'ndid ehs eurt saw tI
ssenkaew fo sngis yna wohs ot dewolla reven saw ehs dna sreh ton erew seciohc reh tuB
uoy htiw yppah oot t’nera snogard rehto ehT
.gnimoc taht ees t’ndid I ,lleW .hO“
.tcapmi ta decniw nniuQ nevE .edis sih otni degrahc dna daeh reh derewol ehs ,revocer dluoc eh erofeB
”.eciohc thgir eht edam uoy ees ot dalg ,lleW“
.noitacilpmoc dednetninu na saw tahT“
”.ecalp eht gnidliuber trats ot eludehcs a dna
detrats yeht ,tfel eceip eno ylno saw ereht dias I
”.tsol teG .ysub s’ehS“
.yaw sih kool ot desufer dna sdnah reh htiw deyalp esylA   .deksa nniuQ
",yleerf kaeps nac ew ,yaw eht fo tuo s'taht won ,lleW“
.rovaf sih niag ot tnemtaert laitnereferp mih evag ehs demialc ynam
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.em detcejer ohw etacitsemod a rof nesohc ym dellik tsuj I“
”.tsil od-ot ym no t’nsaw tahT .ecalp ruoy nwod gninrub rof yrros yas annog m’I tuB
N“   ”.pihs gniknis eht ffo teg ,yas snamuh eht ekiL .flesruoy evaS
,ekarD navE yb ”ammeliD s’nogarD A“ saw sihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?did uoy tahw retfA“
”.dlihc-dliw a htiw laed ot htgnerts eht evah t’nod I .noh ,gniht doog a s’tahT“
,hguone hguorht neeb sah yob roop eht esuac‘ dloraH fo tnorf ni ti yas annaw t’nia I“ .eciov wol a ni ekops dna noihsuc s’nniuQ ot tsesolc riahc eht ni nwod tas ehS ".uoy
.ot taht llet I ohw luferac eb dluow I tuB
.thgin eht fo elddim eht ni reh gnikaw rof erutcel doog a tog eh dna gnihton saw ti dias eh deksa esylA nehW .atnegaR dna mih neewteb deneppah tahw tuoba enoyna dlot reven nniuQ
nialpxe ll’I .egdirb dlo eht yb ruoh na ni em teeM“
,rood eht ot reh derehsu dna dnats ot namow eht degdun eh
”.doog eb retteb tI“
.deksa dloraH ”?uoy ekiL“
.dias elacsmaR eht
.hcter mih edam ti dna erofeb ylgnorts siht ti dellems reven dah eH
.ecalp siht rof snalp ynam os evah I
,hcrairtaM eht tcetorp ot nrows lenitnes eht ,tertS taht eciton sih depacse t'ndah tI .thgin lla reh revo dehctaw eh ,hturt nI
.enihw lufnruom wols a tuo tel dna teef sih ta llab a otni delruc ehS
.ylper t’ndid tub erutsop evissergga sih dexaler kraT
.reh ta gnikool mih was ehs nehw detatiseh ehS
.ereh fo tuo teg tsuJ“
siht tuoba gnihtemoS .noisiced a ekam I erofeb yrots lluf eht teg annaw I tuB“
riap eht ta delworg nniuQ
”?esion siht lla si tahW“
.snroh eht neewteb mih dettap dna delims ehS
.dnuow nepo na ot egamad fo tol a od llits dluoc ti tub erif ot ecnatsiser larutan a dah snogarD
.deksa dloraH ”?ereh
.htaerb sih rednu elbmurg ot deunitnoc dna stekcop sih otni sdnah sih devohs nam gnuoy ehT   ”.tneitap eb tsuJ
,egdirb eht no esilaS teem ot emac yad eht nehW
.ffuh deyonna na htiw yawa denrut ehS  ”--eh ,yadoT
nroh revlis eht dezingocer eH
.ezis llams reh etipsed ,dworc eht tsgnoma namow redlo eht dnif ot gnol ekat t'ndid tI
.oot ,tuo tog uoy dalg m'I ,haeY“
”.gred taht tsurt t’noD“
.htaerb sih rednu dias nniuQ
”.deneppah reven ti dneterp tsuj t’nac I .nwod
eb dluoc yob eht nrobbuts woh enoyna naht retteb wenk nniuQ
”.rehtie ,neht uoy ot klat ot tnaw t’now ehS
.tsaf dnuorg gnisol saw kraT tub ,won litnu neve demees elttab ehT
.mih ffo seye reh gnikat ton ,yawa dekcab ehS ".eromyna
ylwols devom yehT
.klat taht fo hguone s'tahT .won ,woN“
.siht ni devlovni gnitteg
.edur eb dluow ti mih dlot esylA tub ,snoitanod eht nruter ot detnaw nniuQ
.gnithgif llits snogard owt eht dehcaorppa neht
.ssem eht saw deciton eh gniht txen ehT
,enola reh tfel eh fi wenk eH
.ylthgils daeh reh denrut ehS
.emoc dah nwot eht raf woh fo rednimer a sa deniatniam saw egdirb eht ,esu fo kcal sti etipseD
.llaw eht ta derats llits tub roolf eht no liat reh deppals dna delworg ehS
,era uoy ohw erac t’nod I
ton m’I tuB“ .dias nniuQ
.dnah reh ni koobeton a htiw sriats eht nwod emac namow redlo eht ,nooS
.edisa deppets dna
”.ti tegrof mih stel eno on dna ti swonk enoyrevE
,moor eht tfel ehs sa redluohs reh revo dellac ehS
”.egdirb eht ot teg ew nehw tuo dnif ll’eW“
.eromyna llac taht ekam ot teg t’nod uoy taht si emaf gnivah htiw melborp ehT .ees ll’eW“   ".on
.rood tnorf eht rof nar dna pu depmuj eH   ”.on ho—ehs ,haeY“
saw ehS .esilaS taht tsurt t’nod I“
”.ti yas ot deracs oot era tub yawyna enog reh ees ot stnaw enoyreve yltsoM
.detrons dloraH   .dias nniuQ
.egdirb eht no detiaw yeht sa mih detnuah thguoht tahT   .enog saw ti woN
",em ot tseb-dnoces reven saw eH"
.tuo flesti nrub ti tel dna ti niatnoc ot saw noitca fo esruoc ylno ehT
”.rewsna ruoy evah ll’I
,yvaeh gnihtemos gniggard fi sa ylwols gnivom
...morf uoy pots ot emac I“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw ,god.ecioveht
.redluohs sih revo dekool tertS
niap fo sraor dna ,slworg egavas
,eiskooB ,yrruFoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”.uoy wohs annaw I gnihtemos s’erehT .klat fo dnik taht fo hguone s’taht tuB“
.egnar gnikirts fo tuo deniamer tub
.esnes edam ti won tub ,ti ot noitnetta hcum diap t'ndah eh ,tsrif tA
.egatnavda reh ot ti gnisu dna regral saw elamef ehT
.hsa fo elip a emoceb ,emoh sih
"?thgir ,enola er'uoY
.ecaf reh ffo elims eht depiw tahT
.seceip otni dehsams neeb dah saw ereht erutinruf elttil tahW
.sdnoces ni moor eht hguorht daerps semalf eht dna
.tnev yob eht tel ot retteb saw ti dediced nniuQ tub ,dias saw tahw naht no gniog erom saw erehT
.dias I tahw tuoba knihT
”.esoprup no mih htiw thgif a dekcip ehs fi em esirprus t’ndluow tI
,mihllik erad t’ndluow ehS
,drawrof dehsup dna roolf eht otni swalc sih gud eH
,gnidliub eht ta gnikool diova ot drawrof deunitnoc nniuQ
”,reh troppus ot em sksa dna retfa gnol ton em ot semoc ehs neht dnA“
.seye rieht ni etacitsemod a s’tahT .nalc a edistuo namuh a yb desiar erew uoY
.tnemtaert emas eht steg ecalp ym ta enoyrevE
.rof gnithgif sevil eritne rieht dneps tsum yeht thgirhtrib a ynam ot dna
.eciov yrd ,wol a ni deksa ehs
”?on yas I fi neppah lliw tahw ,ytisoiruc fo tuo tsuJ“
,gnol gnipeek no detsisni eh taht riah kcalb ysaerg emas eht dah eh dna elap llits saw niks siH
.revo gnihtemos gnikconk tuohtiw gnihtaerb deraef eh neht neve dna
.ecalp t’ndluoc nniuQ taht seye sih ni ssendas fo kool a saw erehT
.detnaw ap sih maerd eht t'nsaw tahT
.doolb fo loop a ni kraT yal renroc raf eht nI
.dexaler ehs litnu kcen reh no pirg sih denethgit eH
.gnikaerb eciov sih ,dias dloraH
.uoy ot klat annaw I ,yllautca doog s'tahT
rof drah os dekrow eh tnaruatser eht gniruoved semalf gniraor eht fo dnuos ehT .ti ecalp ot tnaw t’ndid eH
yawa hguone raf devom dah dlihc eht dna esylA niatrec saw eh litnu rood eht revo draug doots nniuQ   ”.noh ,luferac eB“
.tey peelsa nellaf ton dah
.niaga semag ruoy otni tnaruatser ym gard uoy tel t’now I dnA
,hcrairtaM a tuohtiw ezilaer od uoY
.noihsuc sih otni knas dna dehgis nniuQ   ”.seye
”?noh ,yako gnihtyreve sI“
.ecaf eht ssorca drah nniuQ deppals-
,emalf hcum t'nsaw erehT
.yletal sremotsuc nogard fo rebmun eht ni noitcuder a deciton eh reh llet ot traeh eht evah t'ndid eH
”,nerdlihc-dliw fo gnikaepS“
”.gnihtyna wonk t’nod uoY .naem I tahw wonk t’nod uoY“
”.ereht revo s’eh ,haeY“   .deksa eh
”.rof depoh ev’dluoc esilaS gniht tseb eht si nwod ti denrub kraT tahT
.guh kciuq a nniuQ evag eH
.thgir s’ehs tub ,ti yas ot etah I“ .dias esylA
dah eH .evom t’ndid dna gnihton dias nniuQ
.kcen sih dnuora ylthgit smra reh depparw dna mih otno flesreh werht ehs ,mih was esylA tnemom ehT
”.taht ekil pu em tes ehs eveileb t’nac I“
,detrons dna degdub t’ndah dloraH dna nniuQ deciton ekard delacs-kcalb ehT
.emoh s'nogard a bor ot hguone dlob erew ynam ton dna
,ecaps fo kcal eht htiw od ot gnihton dah ti taht semit lareves demialc ehS
”?no taht thguorb tahW“ .pu tas nniuQ
”.elihw a rof siht gninnalp neeb s’ehS
.dedeen eh esnopser eht lla saw tahT
****   ”.kcab meht sdloh regnol on hcrairtaM eht nehw
.tliub saw eno retteb ,regral a erofeb nwot eht ot ecnartne lanigiro eht saw egdirb dlo ehT
gnibrutsid a ekil tsomla sriahc dna selbat eht fo sniamer deggaj eht yb dednuorrus
denrub neeb evah ssenisub ym dna esuoh yM“
”.rehtie atnegaR gnitroppus ton m’I
!?meht otni nettog s’tahW“
.kcab kool t’ndid tub esion eht ta decniw eH
”.mih no ffo gnibbur m’I ydaerla dna shtnom wef a su htiw neeb ylno s’eH“
.revo trats ot seilppus wen emos teg tsael ta ro
”,tsrif atnegaR ot klat dluohs I ebyaM“
.erif no tes neeb dah ti erofeb tnaruatser eht fo tol a mih dednimer tI
sselboj dna sselemoh era I dna dloraH
****   .ecalp s’atnegaR rof gnidaeh ,ffo koot dna sgniw sih daerps eh ,edistuo saw eh tnemom ehT
.dehcaorppa eh sa nirg ediw reh was eh ,ecnatsid a morf nevE
.meht fo rebmun hguone egral a ot ylppa ot dah ti ,nwot ni snogard eht lla ot ylppa t'ndid ti fi nevE
.tertS ot denrut dna mih derongi elamef ehT   .deksa dloraH
.mih egnahc dluoc I thguoht dna
.ekawa llits uoy ees ot gnitcepxe t'nsaw ,hO“
”ammeliD s'nogarD A“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
.namuh eht dna reh neewteb deppets nniuQ
”--ot boj reh s’ti ,hcrairtaM eht sA
”?gnorw od I did tahW .siht htiw gnilaed etah I“
egar a ni nwod ecalp eht raet ot mih detnaw uoY
.tnedicni tuohtiw gnidliub eht fo tuo teg ot elba erew tub
,reklatsthgiN elamef A   ”.tiaw t’nac
egnellahc dluoc wef taht rewop fo lobmys A .deraef dna derimda snogard eht gnihtemos saw hcrairtaM ehT .dootsrednu eh won tub ,ti tuoba laed gib a hcus edam snogard eht yhw dna
”?ytip yna uoy wohs ot gniog m’I kniht uoy dna ,uoy fo esuaceb emoh ym tsol tsuj I“
.gninraw yldneirf a gnivig tsuj saw I .won ,aohW“
”.ytip ruoy rof ksa t’ndid I“
.nesohc reh si eh fi erac t’nod I“   ”--uoy era ,noH“   ”.atnegaR ees ot deen I“
.wols ylgnizinoga yb tnew syad eerhT
.llaw eht otni gnileer mih gnidnes ,liat-nroh eht tsniaga ydob reh werht ehS
gninniw saw ohw llet ot drah saw tI
,oot lliw yeht ,hcrairtaM sa em kcab uoy fi tuB
?yako ,esylA htiw ereh yatS
.em troppus ot uoy tnaw I dna ,hcrairtaM sa atnegaR egnellahc ot nalp I
.nageb nniuQ "—ton s'tahT“
”.nwod pets dna mialc ym tpecca ot tub eciohc on evah lliw atnegaR dna
.esylA htiw thgin eht dneps ot "dediced"
setacitsemod ot od snogard rehto eht tahw flesruoy ksA“
?moor rehto eht otni kcab etarc eht gard uoy nac ,noh ,dloraH
.dekcerw saw tnaruatser ehT
”?ereh gniod uoy era tahW“
.syad eerht ni egdirb dlo eht ta neppah dluow tahw tuoba kniht ot ton deirt dna
”?sgred eht tuoba tahw tuB“ .dias dloraH
yawa mih dnes ot duorp oot saw I esuaceB
,wohs t’nod uoy fI .syad eerht retfa ereh kcab emoc ll’I
.reh dniheb rood eht demmals dna edisni deraeppasid atnegaR
”?uoy tuohtiw od I dluow tahW .esylA ,uoy knahT“
.mih tif sehtolc sih dna thgiew erom no tup dah yob eht tub
.ti fo trap a ydaerla er’uoY“
.eciov wol a ni dias neht niaga dnuora dekool ekard ehT
.emit erom yna gnitsaw diova ot tniop eht ot thgiarts teg dna tsrif og ll'I" .dias esilaS
.deid ev’dluoc enoemoS ?no gniog s’tahw wonk neve ehs seoD .cinap
.dnuorg sih doots nniuQ tub resolc deppets ehS
.ewa ni etarc eht ta derats nniuQ   ”.dliuber
dloraH ro esylA rehtie taht gnitacidni sriatspu morf thgil eht was eH
dliuber ot hguone ebyaM .sgnivas dah eH
".erom gnikam erew uoy yas ot ecnahc a teg neve t'ndid I
.devlovni gnitteg
.niaga teerts eht no evil dloraH gnittel eh saw yaw oN
,taeh sti tlef eH
.eulb eht tuo reffo reh htiw pu wohs t’nia esilaS sihT .luferac eb tsuj uoY“   ”.pu dda t’nseod
.ni emoc uoy erehw s’tahT
.ti fo esuaceb mih rof pu dnats ot decrof syawla saw atnegaR dna
.worromot kcab emoC“
.yawrood eht ni deraeppa
.ruoh na ni mih teem ot dias eH“
,tertS morf raelc-lla eht teg ot evah I ,tsriF .yob ,ecneitaP“   ”?su morf tnaw ayddahW“   ”.dloraH si sihT
.sih dnuora liat reh depparw dna edis s’nniuQ ot devom ehS
”?kcab reh dniheb sgniht repsihw snogard eht fo tsom kniht uoy od yhW
”.aedi gnorw eht gnitteg enoyna tnaw t’noD
.mih delbuort roivaheb s'atnegaR
.taht tuoba hguone s’taht tuB“
kaew atnegaR dna
.gniht a mih tsoc t’ndluow ti dna fo erac nekat gnieb saw gnihtyreve taht demrofni saw eh
.gnidnats deniamer tub dereggats dna yawa nniuQ devohs eH
.yltfos deksa atnegaR
.dias tertS ”,nialpxe nac I“
.snamuh fo retsulc a ta detniop dna ecarbme eht ekorb ehS
.erac ot mees t’ndid
.trid eht otni kraT dekconk evah dluow eh ,nogard derujni na kcams ot gnitnaw ton rof t’nsaw ti fI
.hcrairtaM s'nwot eht ta demia sdrow eciohc yrev emos saw ti sseug dluoc eh hguoht gniyas saw nam gnuoy eht tahw raeh t'ndluoc nniuQ
”--atnegaR dna uoy neewteb no gniog si revetahW
”?ereh ehs si yhW ?siht si tahW“
.worromot kcab gnimoc rehtob t’noD“
.atnegaR htiw kaeps ot gnivael erofeb dloraH ees ot tnew eH
.ereh rovaf a uoy gniod m’I tub ,gnitatiseh er’uoy teg I ,kooL“
”,tuoba no ’niog neeb s’enoyreve taht ekac wen ruoy tuo yrt ot detnaw htob yehT“   "?deneppah tahW"
pu dnuorg eht morf tnaruatser eht tliub I
”.uoy fo deracs ton m’I“
?noh ,esle yhW“   ”?yhw tuB
.ria fo tsug egral a ni ffo koot ehS ".ecalp
”!ekac fo eceip a tsuj s’tI
.moor eht otni tog neve eh erofeb noitcurtsed eht draeh nniuQ  ekarD navE yb
.tiaw eritne eht rof htaerb sih rednu delbmurg dloraH
.gniht a tuoba yrrow uoy t'nod ,nniuQ
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.erom gnihtoN .kooc I
.derettam ti taht ton—
.moor dedworc ydaerla eht otni etarc egral a gniggard ,deraeppaer ehS
”?ti si dab woh oS“
”.noh ,em yap attog uoy nehw taht rebmemer tsuJ“
.demees ti thginot litnU
.erif a morf gnisir ekoms eht delbmeser
esoprup no ereht tnew uoy wonk I“   ”?’niagA‘ “
.ekard eht ta deralg nniuQ
,reilednahc eht yal moor eht fo retnec eht nI
.reklatsthgiN gnikool-ffurg a ,lenitneS eht dias
.s'atnegaR ta devirra eh nehw gnidnal ro rood eht no gnikconk rehtob t'ndid nniuQ
revlis dna dlog-der eht ,seidob rieht fo gnihsalc ehT
".yats ot ecalpemos su teg dna atnegaR ees ot deen I
”?ynapmoc ’nitcepxe uoY“
”--kniht ay od ohW“
.esnes yna ekam t’nseod taht ,oN—
".ay tiw ’nimoc m'I"
”.re‘ tiw edis ot ay llet tsuj ll’ehS ?yhW“
.yaw taht niamer dluow ehs
.gnitadimitni dna gnitanicsaf dnuof nniuQ ecnedifnoc fo arua lausu reh evah t’ndid atnegaR
tnaruatser eht dliuber nac eW !si tI“
.denworf dna pu dekool ylneddus eH
”.nwod meht mlac nac I fi ees annog m’I
”.enif s’gnihtyrevE .peY“
.emoclew erew snogard dna snamuh erehw ecalp a ekam dluow eh ,tahw rettam oN
.tnaw uoy snoitseuq eht lla ksa nac uoy neht
.sdrow sih htiw luferac erom eb dluohs yllaer eh tuB
.mih sdrawot yllaicepse—erofeb yldloc taht detca reven dah ehS
”!saw ti naht retteb neve
.meht neewteb ecaps eht htiw ton—ti tneverp ot sselrewop saw eh wenk eh dna
.thginot tuoba erac I sgniht owt gnisol eldnah dluoc I kniht t'nod I"
tub atnegaR tuoba tnaw uoy tahw yaS
thgiew dna mutnemom sih htob gnisu dna swaj sih ni kcen reh fo kcab eht gnizies ,elacsmaR eht dehsur nniuQ
”.kool uoy naht rebmud er’uoy nehT“
.deknilb dna daeh reh detlit ehS
.dias dloraH ”,ti od t’noD“
”?enoyreve gnissarah si kraT tluaf ym ti si woH
.kcab dloraH dna nniuQ gnicrof ,drawrof dellorts lenitneS ehT   ”!tiaW“
-liat s’elamef eht ylekil—gnihtemoS
”ammeliD s’nogarD A“
:ksa attog I ,tsrif tuB"
.edis s’nniuQ dettap ehs ,daetsnI
,nwod reh gninrut retfa nevE .etam nesohc reh eb ot mih deksa ecno dna mih dekil ehs terces on saw tI
,esle enoyreve ekil yap uoy
”.’nimaercs detrats elpoep ecno yzarc tog tI“
,daoR layoR ,trAtnaiveD
.devirra eh nehw ereht ydaerla saw esilaS   .depoh eh os ro
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tnaruatser eht ta kraT thguof dah taht elacsmaR eht saw ekard eht dniheB
,thguac ylkciuq sirbed nedoow eht tub
,ruoh na ni yb emoc ot dlot erew yehT
,seires ysatnaf eht setirw ohw ,ekarD navE yb
.doolb htiw gnippird sehctarcs ni derevoc erew meht fo htoB
”?atnegaR llik annog er’uoY ?tahW“   ".em
nmad taht eveileb t’naC“
.deddon dna dehgis ylno eh os
.srebme yarts rof hctaw ot sgnidliub gnirobhgien eht no gnidnal dna
dab kool atnegaR ekam ot ti esu dluoc uoy os
.peels ot og ot emit saw ti litnu dehgual dna knard dna eta yeht dna rennid edam neve ehS
pleh ot yppah naht erom eb ll’yeht
,sbir s'kraT nekorb t'ndah wolb taht fI .revo saw elttab sihT   .smar gnirettab laedi meht gnikam
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.meht no ni netsil ot dnuora saw eno on demrifnoc dna denruter tertS erofeb gnol ekat t’ndid tI
".’niog m'I"   "--dloraH"
.uoy gnithgif otni kraT ekovorp ot
”.em fo tuo gnihton teg uoy ,mih truh uoy fI“
.lortnoc s’hcrairtaM eht ot lartnec erofereht dna nwot eht fo trap lartnec a saw eh ,ton ro ti ekiL .rovaf sih ni demees emoctuo rehtien nehw yllaicepse
.hcrairtaM emoceb I nehw uoy htiw gnikrow ot drawrof kool I"
?kraT gnillortnoc emit drah a hcus sah atnegaR kniht uoy od yhW
?doog nwo ruoy rof trams oot er’uoy uoy llet reve enoynA“
eht noitnem ot toN“ .dias nniuQ
tegdub a tuo krow annog m'I
nogard dliw a ekil kool kraT ekam oT
”.atnegaR troppus dluohs uoy kniht I tub
.ti dliuber ot stsoc ti hcum revewoH
.em ot rettam t’nseod tahT“   ”.hcrairtam a
dewob lenitneS ehT
nehW" .ylikahs dias namow redlo eht
.edis sih dettap dna resolc devom ehS
”,yako rey dalG“
fo trap on detnaw eh emag emos ni desu gnieb ekil t’ndid eH
,yad dnoces eht yB
.retal kcab emoc t’nac I“   ”.retal kcab emoC“
yeht ,og ot erehwon htiW
.deppord waj sih ,llah gninid niam eht dehcaer eh ecnO
.ruos denrut noisserpxe s’esilaS   .deksa dloraH
.won evael t’ndid yeht fi meht no nwod emoc dluow gnidliub ehT
”.uoy truh reven d’yehT“
"?scitilop fo tuo yats
.nrut sih tiaw t’ndluoc eh esuaceb
.relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
****   ".wonk I"   .derepsihw ehs
”,sklof ecin ytterP“
.gnihtyna naht desufnoc erom ,yawa deklaw eh sa gnihton dias nniuQ   ”.neht
”.enola eb ot tnaw I .evael woN
.ecalp s'esylA ot kcab deklaw nniuQ
.mih gnillortnoc ton rof
,gnimoc saw tahw wenk nniuQ .lavir sih ta sreggad eralg ot deunitnoc tub ria rof gnipsag ,roolf eht no yal kraT
.noisivid fo eceipretnec a eb ton ,slaem suoiciled gnikam fo evol sih erahs
.thgin eht fo tser eht regnif a tfil nniuQ tel t’ndid dna drow reh ot eurt saw esylA
siht tub ,ysub si atnegaR dnatsrednu I“
.reh dekcatta dna yzarc tnew eh erofeb kraT ot gniklat
.tsehc reh ni ecaf s’dlihc eht deirub dna demaercs ehs dna ,hsarc a dna lworg a emac erehT
.redluohs reh revo elims yls a evag dna deppots ehS
,tem tsrif yeht nehW .mih gnizingocer emit drah a dah nniuQ
.moor eht fo tuo ti ekam t'ndid ohw enoyna rof moor eht dennacs dna
.gnorw er'uoy erehw s'tahT"
.sgniw reh daerps dna wol dehcuorc ehs ,ecaps hguone dah ehs ecnO
,ti dnuora hcnert a gniggid ,gnidliub eht gnilcric nugeb ydaerla dah snogard rehtO
.ecneserp s’nniuQ fo noitcejer yna wohs t’ndid dna ecnedifnoc htiw deklaw ehS
.ylf emosrehtob a yawa gnisahc fi sa liat reh devaw ehS
”?ecalp ruoy gnitcetorp eno on s’ereht
.tnaruatser eht rof kcab diap er’uoy erus ekam ll’I“
.on s'rewsna eht tub derettalf m'I"
.eciohc a fo hcum evah t’nod eW“
”.taht od ot naht retteb wenk tsael ta ehs
.yawa denrut tub tnaruatser eht ta dekool tsomla eH ".oot
.ot detnaw ehs raelc saw ti hguoht dnopser t’ndid esylA   ”.nrut
.snoitaitogen eht eldnah daeh relooc a htiw enoemos tel ot retteb saw ti nam gnuoy eht decnivnoc eh tub
.nogard nworg a rof ecaps gnivah ton reh tuoba snoitcejbo s'nniuQ etipsed dediced ehs ,hturt nI
.ti revo gnithgif
renroc eht ni lruc dluoc eh os tsuj degnarraer eb ot dah moor gnivil reh fo flaH
”,ygolopa ruoy tpecca I“
?ew llahs ,snoitcudortni eht hguorht teg s’tel ,taht gnildnah s’eh elihW“
.nniuQ ot kcab denrut ehs ,ffo welf ekard eht ecnO
”.eslE .enO .yreve ekil
.ssa eht ni niap a hcus si kraT tluaf ruoy s’ti swonk enoyreve dna
".srovaf yna rof gniksa tuohtiw nwo ym no
.kraT ot tnew dna reh derongi eH
”.uoy rof llew dne t’now foorp tuohtiw em gnisucca ylcilbuP
”.nioc hcum os
.gnihton dias tub denworf dloraH
,gniretnilps doow dna ssalG
nroht a neeb dah kraT
,rehtegot shtnom lareves retfa nevE
.semalf rehto naht rettoh denrub erif nogard dnA .regnuh sti
.rotcaf llams a deyalp ti detcepsus eh tub
****     ".og s'teL .thgir llA"
.flesmih ti dliub dluoc eh erofeb deid ohw ap sih fo yromem ni tliub neeb dah tnaruatser tahT
.dliub ot drah os dekrow dah eh emoh eht fo sniamer deniur eht ta kool ot dnats t’ndluoc osla eH
,slluks rekciht dna
.tnaw I sa gnol sA“
.lortnoc fo tuo si kraT ,atnegaR“   ”.uoy ot kaeps ot detnaw namuh sih dna ekard sihT“
.llaw eht ta gnirats ,moor eht fo elddim eht ni tas atnegaR
?uoy t’nera ,eno dlob a er’uoY“
nac uoy kniht uoy od gnol woH .rekaterac namuh a fo tep ydobon eht erew uoy nehw kcab saw tahT“ .denworf esilaS
.srood rieht no skcol htiw derehtob reven meht fo lla tsomla dna swodniw dekcal semoh rieht fo ynam ,dliw eht ni gnivil ot desu erew snogard tsom esuaceB
.nesohc reh sa uoy detnaw ehs yhw ees I"
.gniklat enod er’eW“   ”—tuB“   ”.ysub m’I
.deeps lluf ta rood eht rof thgiarts evod eH
.liaT-nroH revliS a dna elacsmaR a ,snogard owt erew gnithgif llitS
yojne esaelP  .livnA dlroW dna
.doolb fo llems eht saw deciton eh gniht tsrif ehT
sllah eht gnidoolf srednatsyb eht fo smaercs eht tuo denword
.mih dniheb llef stcejbo lareveS
.swodahs eht morf gniklats syawla saw esilaS a sa
.wodniw eht hguorht epacse elamef eht dehctaw eh sa dereggats eH
”.ni gninetsil eno on s’ereht erus ekam dna dnuora kooL“
.noitautis tnerruc eht ot kcab detfird sthguoht sih dna sriatspu tnew enoyreve retfa gnol tsal t'ndid ssenirrem s'thginoT .regnol elihw elttil a pu deyats nniuQ
.roolf eht gnippals liat gnol sih
.enot latnerap-gnorts a ni detcejretni esylA ”,doof doog meht evres ll’taht selim rof ecalp rehtona t’nia ereht wonk yeht esuaceb enola uoy evael snogard ehT“   ”—
”?dloraH nees uoy evaH“
,nesohc eht emaceb eh ecnis reve edis s'enoyreve ni
tnaem hcrairtaM fo eltit eht tahw tuoba thguoht reven
.meht sdrawot gniklaw ,tertS ,reklatsthgiN eht was dna dnuora nups nniuQ
”,ot kcab og ot erehwon evah I
doof etsaw t’nod uoy dna
”.ekac tsuj naht erom tuoba si siht kniht I tub ,wonk t’nod I“
”.yako er’yeht erus gnikam s’eH
.smra reh ni dlihc namuh a gnidloh ,srenroc eht fo eno ni deldduh esylA dnuof eH
.delworg dna nwod daeh reh dennip eH
.cinap eht ni truh tog sklof elpuoc A“
.sdeew eht otni deraeppasid neht decnuob taht elbbep llams a dekcik eH
”.meht fo dir teg ,tertS
.dehsinav dah ekard eht was tub noitcerid s’kraT ni eralg a tohs eh
.meht revo dehsaw taeh eht sa yawa denrut dna seye sih desolc nniuQ
”.uoy gnitroppus eb t’now I uoy llet ot ereh m’I ,yllautcA“
?tnaruatser eht nwod nrub oT“
.taps kraT ”,em fo ffo teg ,yakO“
”,enoyna ees ot tnaw t’nseod hcrairtaM ehT“
.egrahc fo eerf lwob a reh evig dluow eh ,gnivrats fo egrev eht no pu dewohs ehs fi ,did esilaS tahw etipseD
.dloraH fo tnorf ni deppets nniuQ
s’tahT“ .niaga ti dliuber neht ,nwod ti raet ,dliuber ot hguone naht erom saw erehT
.emit siht raf oot enog s’eH
.swen dab htiw esylA ot kcab og ot tnaw t’ndid nniuQ tub
.roolf eht ot reh gard ot
.steews gnikab gnicitcarp detrats eh yhw nosaer eht saw tI
snroh devruc rieht rof deman os erew selacsmaR
egrahc ni hcrairtaM eht dna emoh eurt tsrif sih tsol tsuj dloraH
.reirrab nedoow eht hguorht dehsams eh nehw egamad eht deziminim ti sa siht rof lufetarg saw nniuQ
”.gnimoc ti dah eH ?yhW“   ”.yrros m’I...morf
’nitteg gred taht s’lleh eht nehW“
”.tnaruatser etirovaf reh nwod denrub eh nrael ot yppah oot eb ll’ehs tbuod I .mih eldnah reh tel tsuj uoY“
.nwod reh denrut uoy esuaceb mih esohc ylno ehs ,nniuQ“
.em stroppus ereh dnuora ytinummoc eht wonk I
.em dnatsrednusim uoY“   ".atnegaR