.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
eno rehtona otnu kool lliw I os
noivilbo detaf-lli na otni pmuls srebmahc tfiwS
.flesym rof esruc teewsrettib a tub
snoisnemid ralletsretnI
esoprup ro emyhr on htiw noitulosba otni desufeR
.nalp ym otni em ynapmocca nac lufesu demeed esoht ylno teY
,oI ot nemo na sesahp gnicar stI
setirw ohw ,ainorkA yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,smeop ciryl
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,ainorkA yb
derutrot dna derenroc
”ytilaeR deliaF A“ saw sihT
dedivid os tey ,detargetni strap ynam os htiw dlrow A ?ksa yam uoy
smees ti ssendam htiw detangerpmi
,rehtegot semoc lla tI
.ytiniffAruF no yrteop sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
noitatroped sih was dna demialc saw dnal stI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,luos yrev sih ecrovid ot nalp suoinegnI nA
,htlaeh latnem sa hcus scipot no setirw netfo eH
,seye ruoy ni esuac tsuj a saw tI
,redrosid latnem a htiw gnivil fo egnellahc eht ro
ylsselicrem snepo taht dnal siht si tI
nwo ym gniyortsed ni dedeeccus sah ytilaer ruoY
,”ytilaeR deliaF A“   yojne esaelP
,em deliaf sah ytilaer yM
ereh evitan ecno saw
llarht detalahxe na nI
nopu klaw tsuj enola I taht htap eht si siht teY
.emarf lellarap ym otno
.elyts esrev eerf a ni yllacipyt
yad fo thgil eht was reven taht epacse nA
neila dehsag ,tilps A
dewodiw eht fo luos eht fo tfel saw tahW  demialcxe yeht
niap a fo ssyba detnemgarF
ainorkA yb meop a
xallarap a otni deknil ssorc
,erutan cixot a fo si dnal sihT
ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot
snoisuled eht stilps ti
bmun dna elap derats stimreh gniracnU