,kcuF“ .hgiht s’gnasT tsniaga gnippolf tfahs depparw sih
.ti eveileb t’ndluoc gnasT ,tnemom a roF
.metsys noitalitnev eht fo knalc elbiduani tsomla eht htiw gnola
tlep dettesor
ssengniogtuo ron ytilibixelf eht rehtien dah eh tub
.bos a htiw mih dnuora smra sih werht
.kcils lla ti teg ot dnuor meht gninrut
.derettuts gnasT ”...mu...I“
s’gnasT otni ylwols flesmih dehsup naibaF ,taht htiw dnA
.noitcafsitas lanrac fo obmoc tih-owt a ,erom ecno gnimmuc mih tog eugnot s’naibaF
.elkcuhc a deganam ekiM
,won lufniap ssel raf tlef elohssa s’gnasT ni gnibbaj eht ,hguone ylegnartS
,enohp eht rof ylwols dehcaer gnasT
:yojne esaelP   .egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no
,shtnom gnol ynam ni emit tsrif eht rof
,esaeler eudrevo-gnol fo egarrab tsrif eht htiw enod saw eh thguoht gnasT sa dnA
derettam esle gnihton
.snoitacilbuP tenalPruF yb dehsilbup
llac I esoht gnoma uoy tnuoc t’nod I naem t’nseod taht tub ,ti gniyned on yllaer s’ereht ,worra na sa thgiarts m’I“ .delkcuhc ekiM
.htiw noitasrevnoc siht gnivah
fo strap 2 fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.tes lla er’uoy dna rdnirG no em dda tsuJ .enif s’taht ,niaga siht ekil rehtegot teg ot tnaw reve uoy fi tuB
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
.emoh ruo ta uoy emoclew ot yppah naht erom er’yeht ,taht rof dna
,ekatsim taht nees evah dluohs eh tlef gnasT
.drawrof gum sih dehcaer netram ehT
sledom TRC yxob redlo esoht fo eno saw VT eht nevE
?gniod s’eh woh ksa ot dnuor emac llits ekiM
”.won nrut ym s’ti ,lleW“
.smelborp ruoy rof rae gninetsil a ton
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.ecnelis ni setunim wef a rof ereht yal meht fo owt ehT
,enim uoy dewohs I tuB
”,ti evah uoy fi ,etalocohc toH“
os gnihtemos tuoba tnorfpu dna tcerid siht reve saw tem d’eh eno oN
,gnihtemos yas ot detnaw gnasT ”.yalp s’tel oS“
,emit a ta owt sriats eht nwod tnew gnasT
.gnithgil ni egnahc eht ta gniknilb seye sih
.taorht sih morf gnitaname rrup wol a
”,thgit dna ecin laer meht sekaM
.eceiprae eht hguorht emac eciov s’ekiM ”?ereht llits uoY“
,tfel netram eht retfa did eh tahw tuoba ekiM dlot eh oS
,desserd tog ylkciuq gnasT
,mih otni sregnif detacirbul
.siht ot wen er’uoy teg I ,tik ,kooL“
.mih edisni gnidaerps htmraw a tlef evah ylbaborp dluow eh ,modnoc eht rof ton ti erew dna
,yrruh ralucitrap yna ni saw gnasT ekil t’nsaw tI
,floWisakiM yb ”retniW nI dneirF A“
.mih pleh ot deirt dah ekiM .eno on ton ,lleW
.mih ekil ynroh dna yag osla saw nosrep eht taht tcaf elos eht yb
”?eeffoc ro aet tnaw uoY“
.emoc ot saw tahw rof mih gnisae
.retemillim yb retemillim ,rekcup dehcnelc
.ereh ytilaitnedifnoc no swal tcirts yllaer
.ecnartne sih gniddorp tfahs sih
.hcum os mih gnilbuort saw tahw gnasT ksa ot traeh eht dah eh esuaceb lla
shtnom eseht lla retfa
.elims a htiw denrut eh sa weiv morf yawa gnuws sllab s’raugaj ehT ”?ispeP ?ekoC ?reeB
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,lla ti denigami dah eh fi derednow gnasT
mih desucca dah gnasT
.ti teg I ,elgna teg ot drah eht gniyalp dna ,eno etuc a er’uoy ,kooL“
.snalp noitavoner sti ni dniheb rehtruf neve demees taht kcolb mrod redlo na saw etaG s’nedlE  2# fo
,drapoel eht tsap yaw sih edam eh sA .erats drah
2# traP ,floWisakiM yb
.niaga enola lla saw gnasT won dna ,esac eht eb ot ton
,emoh kcab thgilf ym dellecnac I taht
”?won od ot tnaw uoy od tahw…oS“
.eb nac sa nialp sa saw elohssa sih fo sseneros dna retaews sih no pir eht tub
emit eht ssap ot snaem a sa tac drapoel eht gnisu fo
;htob syub etammoor eht yhw erus toN“
.revetahw ro yranoissim ro laro did yeht rehtehw dna ,mohw dekcuf d’ohw
”.etunim a no gnah ,seY“
.pu denesool neeb d’eh retfa neve tnasaelp
”?retnec ytic eht ta knird a barg…mre…ot tnaW“
,s’ekiM tsniaga gum sih deppat dna
.tuoba klat ot esle gnihtemos rof thguos gnasT
.htaerb a koot netram eht
esor tsehc s’gnasT
,deltsihw elttek ehT
?ekil leef dluow taht woh gninigami ylno fo
”?gnihtemos ro tsrif modnoc a no tup esaelp uoy nac ,tiaW“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.sllab erab s’dilef eht naht rehto
gnasT dna ,dias naibaF ”,tihsllub yalperof siht fo hguone ,thgirlA“
elttil ,ti s’tahT“
,tsuj s’tI .ylimaf ruoy htiw no gniog s’tahw uoy deksa I yrros m’I ,kooL .gnasT ,iH“
nevorp d’ti taht ylnO
,mrod eht ot rood eht ta doots raugaj ehT
.tsrif klat dluoc ew thguoht I“
,tsurht retfa tsurht evag naibaF sa gnola gnicnuob
,tfahs sih fo pit eht nopu thguac snaej sih fo dnabtsiaw eht sa delwoy gnasT ,won yb drah elttil a gnieB .denmad eb tleb
daetsni tub ,smelborp sih rof rae gninetsil a dnuof yllanif d’eh thguoht d’eH
,tnecs s’yug siht tuoba ecin gnihtemos saw ereht ,neht tuB
.seye sih dellor raugaj ehT
.denworf gnasT ”?...uoy era
,gnasT morf puc eht detpecca eh sa smra sih dessorcnu ekiM
”.gniht emas eht yllacisab s’ispeP dna ekoC
.hcuoc eht no won saw ylleb s’tac drapoel eht taht hcus
.did eh sa ffo modnoc sih gnileep ,pu tog naibaF
,elohssa s’gnasT edisni debborht dna deslup kcoc s’naibaF
,gnar enohp s’gnasT
.siht fo tuo teg ot gnihtyna
.em tuoba skniht ylimaf ym tahw diarfa m’I esuaceb si supmac ni llits m’I yhw nosaer eht ,lleW“
.woem a htiw hcuoc eht no kcab llaf mih edam sgel sih htob no knay drah a tub
rednow gnasT dah taht thgil eht ni devom settesor sih yaw eht tuoba gnihtemos
.did eh tahw ta doog yllaer saw naibaF tub
.ecalp tsrif eht ni emoh kcab yag eb ot saw ti laed gib a tahw wonk dluow rollesnuoc eht rehtehw ro
,tihs ekil tlef gnasT
taht ta og a evah ot ygrene eht gnivah flesmih enigami t’ndluoc tub
.ylleb s’gnasT no tap a evag eH
.ti hguorht teg ot srehto morf pleh deen ew semitemos ,evah yam ew smelborp revetahW .gnasT ,netsiL“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yleritne esle gnihtemos detnaw yug siht
,tnemom a rof dnA .deffins gnasT
.delkcuhc raugaj ehT
”!ni no emoc ,nam yeH“
Y“ .noitautis tnerruc sih nevig
.ton fi yats ot ecalp a dna ,sruoy htiw thgir sgniht ekam ot yrt ot stnerap ym teg nac I fi ees ll’I taht hguone dneirF .dneirf
.deirrow gnikool elzzum sih
”?emoh kcab ylimaf ruoy s’woh ,oS“
,syaw rehto ni xes dah osla nem wenk eH
fo strap 2# fo 2# eht eht saw sihT       .saw eh ohw rof
.erofeb ti deirt evah reve ot
.tfahs gninaw-yldipar sih morf muc fo spord gniniamer eht gninaelc naibaF fo erawa yleugav saw tac drapoel eht dna
,uoy tem t’nevah yeht fi uoy rof pu kaeps ot stnerap ym rof drah s’ti tuB
,thgirb os erew seye s’ekiM
.ffur keehc sih dekorts dna
”?mmh ,sruoy em wohs uoy tuoba woh os
.roolf dnoces eht ot spets nedoow ykaerc eht pu yaw sih edam dna mocretni eht ta ypp4H yb ni dezzub tog eH
,drah tlef tac drapoel ehT
,tnemom siht erofeb gnol os tiaw ot diputs os saw eh yhw derednow eH
,elbignatni dna raelc snoitome fo yrrulf a ni gnidolpxe ydob sih ,delwoy tac drapoel ehT
.egdirf dna elbat eht no deen I tahw tog ev’I“
,gum eht otni stnetnoc sti deruop gnasT dna
enoder yltnecer dekool roiretxe eht no gnipacsdnal ehT
.htrig s’naibaF fo enoemos etadommocca ot denoitidnoc ylerab rekcup sih ,delley
nmuloc sa seye sih erofeb gnicnad thgil fo skraps
.kcab sih tsniaga mraw raugaj eht fo tsehc eht
.yaw eht yb ,gib yllaer m’I“
.noitativni s’netram eht nwod nrut ot mih rof elbissopmi saw ti dna
.dnuora em htiw syawla ton hguoht ,raey yreve taht seod ylimaf yM
,revo mih deppilf dna delworg naibaF
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,rood eht ni tes ssalg eht ta
.did eh sa kcen sih gnipsar eugnot sih
”.gnimoc erofeb reeb klim emos dah ydaerla I ,sknaht oN“
.retteb dna rediw senifnoc s’gnasT gnihcterts
,tcejbo xes a sa mih was ylno eh dettimda yllacitcarp raugaj ehT
,ygolohtnA 01 GNAF eht ni deraeppa ylremrof evah ”RETNIW NI DNEIRF A“
”.noitiut ym gnillecnac ot dnuor teg ylimaf ym dluohs
.gum sih morf pis a koot ekiM
.kcab eht ssorca gnasT dekorts eh sa ylniatrecnu ekiM dehtoos
”?gnikrow t’nsaw mocretni eht denoitnem uoY .rood tnorf eht ta m’I ?klat
”.gnileef doog a yltcaxe t’nsi emosenol s’eno no eB
.deilper gnasT ”,s’tel ,haey-
,esu evisnetxe was taht ecalp a fo sgnikam eht dah moor nommoc ehT
.emac tsuj yeht nehw skniwt kcuf ot ekil I“
htaerb sih morf emac reeb fo tnecs tniaf A
nac tuB .ylimaf eht ees ot kcab og ot aedi taerg a s’ti kniht t’nod uoy yhw teg neve thgim I
”.reve ton ,won toN .meht tuoba klat ot tnaw t’nod I
.tfahs sih no dehcnelc elohssa s’gnasT sa dehgis naibaF ”,tac
weiv nialp ni doots netram ehT
.erom ebyam dna ,smelborp sih tuoba gniklat ot elbanema erom eb d’eh ,detnaw eh tahw yug siht evag eh fi ebyaM
”,enola siht raeb ot evah dluohs enoyna kniht t’nod I ,wonk uoy
rae gninetsil a dnif ot stroffe sih taht eveileb t’ndluoc gnasT
delims tac drapoel eht ,taht htiw dnA
,elttob a morf ebul fo stol htiw kcoc elbazis sih gnirehtal
”.gnireenignE liviC morf naibaF m’I dnA“
eveileb ot hguone deretnec-fles saw eh esuaceb spahrep tub ,dlrow eht ni dneirf ylno sih neeb evah thgim tahw ot elohssa etelpmoc a neeb d’eh esuaceb ton
.won rof enif mih stiuS
!enilno ti tuoba erecnis os neeb d’eh dnA
,cirbaf kciht eht ni gnippir emos raeh dluoc eh erows eH
.enola ihzgnoD naem I—
,mrod tnelis dna dloc sih
.esrow sgniht ekam tsuj flesruoy ot smelborp gnipeeK
”.scimonocE morf gnasT m’I
.yaw rieht og dluohs gnihtyreve ekil gnitca syawla
”!ydaerla ffo sehtolc ruoy teG“
,gnidliub nredom erom a ni gnivil fo stsoc eht droffa dluoc tneduts yreve ton derugif gnasT
,puc a ni thguob dah etammrod rehtona redwop aococ emos nettog dah gnasT nehW
,trapa sgel s’gnasT dloh ot dedeecorp neht eH
.eye-ot-eye sgniht emos ees tsael ta ll’yeht os ,noitareneg emas eht fo htob era stnerap ruo tuB
,esirprus ni deneffits netram ehT
,elkcuhc a htiw naibaF deksa
”.tey tsedloc eht fo eno s’retniw siht yas yehT
.eceiprae eht ot denetsil dna
.tfahs sih ssorca htmraw neddus eht ta gnipsag tac drapoel eht
”—klat neve ton tub kcuf saw od ot detnaw eh lla daetsni dna ,rdnirG no dneirf a gnidnif yrt ot dediced I taht desserped dna ylenol os saw I dna
,ot kcab emoc ot ytisrevinu a evah neve ton thgim I
,plug eno ni rebmem s’gnasT deflugne htuom sih ,fo kaeps ot gninraw on htiW
,kcen s’dilef regral eht fo tlep eht ssorca gnihctarcs eugnot ypsar sih
tceffa ot kcab teg dluow ti rehtehw wonk t’ndid eh ,parc ytilaitnedifnoc tneduts eht lla htiw neve esuaceb ,ylniatrec ,rollesnuoc loohcs eht toN
,gnidliub mrod nwo sih ot dloc eht hguorht deklaw eh sa nevE
”.taht rof gnah og nac ylimaf uoY .llew ,haeY“
.tmaerd evah reve dluoc ro
.kaelb dna niatrecnu dekool regnol on taht erutuf A
.eb ot tuo denrut taht dneirf a gnidnif ta tpmetta emoS
.og ot esle erehwyna evah t’nod I tub ,ekiM ,taht teg I“ .dias ekiM
,deretne gnasT sa edisa devom eH
,won roF .emoc ot noos
,raugaj regnorts eht morf eerf kaerb ot epoh reven dluoc gnasT ,thgim eh sa yrT
,setatS eht ni yllaicepse tsom dna nawiaT ni kcab nrop fo tol a dehctaw d’eH
dloc lareves dils raugaj eht sa derevihs gnasT
.erom rof moor edam eh sa gniplug taorht sih
.retaw emos liob ot elttek eht tes dna moor nommoc eht ot pu ekiM del eH
,tsaf os deneppah naibaF htiw tnedicni ehT
,wA“ .gnitrams ti gnivael
.moor eht gnillif amora ylemoh a
.ebul fo gnirehtal rehtona yb dewollof
.ecnemehev sih ta kcohs ni derats gnasT
”?sey yas uoy tuoba woh oS
”?erom rof ydaer uoY“
,dilef regral eht fo waj eht htaeneb elzzun ot dedeecorp eh os
”—ees uoy ,kcab skeew wef a yag m’I tuo dnuof yehT
thgirpu elbbarcs ot edam eH
,erofeb enoyna htiw xes dah t’ndah gnasT
,ekatsim a naht erom gnihton neeb dah enod d’eh tahw taht leef ydaerla dluoc eh ,regnol yna pu tnep t’nsaw tac drapoel eht taht woN
,yas ot gnihtemos fo deen rof ,deksa gnasT
?reilrae tuoba no gniog er’uoy tahw em llet uoy
.no ebul eht tog eh sa naibaF detnurg
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.reilrae siht lla enod evah eh dluohs
,ssa denot-llew taht ta gnikool tsiser etiuq t’ndluoc eh tub
”.rof ereh yttik ym tog ev’I tahw s’tahT“ .delbmum naibaF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”?hcum yrev taht ekil yttik elttiL“
?seog pihsdneirf rof hcraes s’gnasT woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
gnasT tub ,denepo rood eht sa nageb ekiM
”?thgirla ,nwod eltteS .dneirf ym ,nwod elttes ,aohW“
.rehtona eno ssorca tis ot afos eht ot tnew meht fo owt ehT
.thgir os ,lufrednow
.elbat eht no ecaps eht lla pu koot dna noituloser parc dah taht
,gnixaler eb dluohs eh taht sediuq pleh-fles enilno morf wenk eH
ezilaer ot stnemom lareves gnasT koot ti dna
.htiw pu emoc ot eganam uoy lleh eht revetahw tuoba ezeerb eht toohs dna klat llams
.opmet s’raugaj eht ot ycnegru niatrec a leef dluoc gnasT dna ,revewoh ,deggar dna wol gnimoc detrats shtaerb s’naibaF
.htiw nigeb ot smelborp sih dnatsrednu dluow eh naht rehto eno on
.cirbaf fo yrrulf a ni delgnat smra sih
retteb yna leef mih ekam yltcaxe t’ndid edistuo ria eht fo dloc ehT
nwonk flesti gnikam ysatsce fo strups
,hself revo gnibbur rebbur fo dnuos eht yb dewollof
,dexamilc eh sa mih ot gnasT gnidloh ,deffuh naibaF
os gnihtemos leef ot detcepxe eh dah smaerd tsedliw sih ni reveN
.ed-aM .kcuF .deirc dna
”.ekiM ,sknahT .won od I“
,rdnirG hguorht puteem a egnarra uoy nehw tuB
ekam uoy ,dliw eht ni ereht tuo enoemos teem uoy nehW
s’naibaF erongi ot tseb sih gniyrt
,gniht a ees t’ndluoc tac drapoel eht tnemom a rof dna
.seye sih gnitreva ,deilper gnasT
mih enigami dluoc gnasT esle enoyna
afos eht otni llef tac drapoel eht
,noitasnes neddus eht ta depsag raugaj ehT
,thgir gnihtemos enod d’eh derugif gnasT
;emit eht ta evah yeht egru ro erised revetahw yfsitas ot elpoep rof ecnahc A
”.os yas ot yhs oot eb t’noD
,erofeb dneirf a fo hcum ekil mees t’ndid I fi yrros m’I“
spahrep taht dediced tac drapoel ehT
,thgirpu kcab tog naibaF
,mih fo tuo dezeeuqs htaerb eht gnileef
.moor nommoc eht morf thgil eht yb detteuohlis
.lla retfa aedi dab a hcus s’ti fi
,retaews dednuofnoc sih fo eerf teg dluoc gnasT erofeB
,tfahs kcils mraw ylralimis nwo sih revo dils wam kcils mraw eht sa denaom gnasT
,owt eht neewteb ecnelis saw ereht
.os ro ruoh txen eht rof tsael ta ,tey tsuj
.swap sih htiw ylkciuq sdrawkcab delffuhs eH
.mih ekil syag sdrawot deretac tpecxe ,sppa aidem laicos ot ralimis erew rdnirG ekil sppa taht derugif dah tac drapoel ehT
eht ni thgir gnasT kool ekiM ”.dnim t’now daD dna muM .ylimaf eht htiw ,wonk uoY .ecalp ym ta syadiloh eht dneps ot tnaw uoy fi gniksa m’I yhw s’taht ,lleW“
.revihs yratnulovni na evag ekiM
,bmuht dehtaehs a htiw noci neerg gniknilb eht depiws eH
,repparw citsalp a fo gnippir eht raeh dluoc eh ,revewoh ,os did eh sA
.uoy rof ereh m’I
ni deveileb eh tahw rof mih gnizicartso ro gnizicitirc saw eno oN .hguone saw taht
gnasT ot revo edorts raugaj ehT ”.dooG
.syadiloh eht retfa sessalc ni netram eht gniteem ot drawrof kool t’ndid eh dna
,elbayojne eb ot desoppus saw laro wenk eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
detnaw dah naibaF lla taht
”.yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I ,ekiM“ .ecaf sih otni gnipeerc hsulb a fo sgninnigeb eht tlef gnasT ?ekiM htiw syadiloh eht dnepS .ti dias eh sa seye
.taht draeh eh sa denettalf srae s’gnasT
,tuo dekcik d’eh netram eht
mih gnitnuom enoemos dah yllanif eh nehw xaler eh dluoc woh tub ,gnihcnelc ton
skeew owt tsal eht rof dessip gnikcuf os tsuj saw I
,gnirednow tsuj ,ekiM“
.mih ot pu emac ekiM
.uoy rof ereh m’I
,siht ekil esolc os dleh gnieb gnihsiler tey
,lla ta gnihtyna ni dalc t’nsaw eh tcaf eht ta erats ot ylno
”.riaf s’taht sseug I ,haey ,rE“
.tsael ta ,ti ot 2SP dlo na tcennoc ot deganam enoemoS
.setammrod sih toN
.tserkcab afos eht no demmals daeh sih taht drah os dekrej eh dna
,tihs ekil mih gnitaert etipseD
.tem sllab s’raugaj eht erehw ruf maerc otni gnirednaem
,reverof siht hsiler dluoc eh dehsiw gnasT
.deddon ylerem gnasT
,nwod yllufecrof stnap sih deknay ydaerla dah naibaF
,mre ,tsuj ew dna pu emoc I naC“
”.tuo dloc nmad s’ti ,sediseB
.gnasT ,enola t’nera uoy tuB“
esle gnihtyna fo kniht ot deliaf dna deirt gnasT ”,mmU“
.mrots lluf ni tuo sbrab sih
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,sthgil eht lla no gninrut
”.ekiM ,dnatsrednu I ,seY“
,pu teg ot edam gnasT
,dellup eh sa retaews s’gnasT fo mottob eht nopu deggans swalc siH
,kcab s’gnasT nopu thgiew eritne sih yal naibaF tub ,kcab elggirw dna tsiwt ot deirt gnasT
ot etaler dluoc eh enoemos
naibaF ees dluoc eh
,revewoh ,dnatsrednu ot demees naibaF
.ydeen dna ypeerc dna driew mih kniht t’ndid netram eht gnihsiw
,erats ot gnorw saw ti wenk gnasT
.yas ot detnaw eh sgniht eht lla morf tsaf dna drah gnihtaerb t’nsaw eh fi derrup evah dluow gnasT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.htiw revo siht teg ot tseb s’ti dediced neht
yldeirrow derats eH
,won llac ot gnisohc yb yrujni ot tlusni rehtruf dda ot gniyrt erew rehtorb ro stnerap sih rehtehw gnirednoW
.sredluohs rellams s’gnasT nopu swap htob decalp raugaj ehT ”.yalp erom
.og ot sgniht detcepxe gnasT woh t’nsaw siht ”...I tuB“
,ti enod yldesoppus d’ohw ssalc ni esoht yb detsetta sa
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
evah yehT .rollesnuoc loohcs eht ot klat syawla dluoc uoy ,dneirf a redisnoc uoy enoyna evah t’nod uoy fi nevE
,rewsna ot etats hcum ni gnieb toN .deksa naibaF
,setis yag eht fo emos no tuoba draeh d’eh sepyt ”mod“ esoht fo eno saw yug eht derugif tub
.sevlesmeht smelborp fo erutan eht saw taht spahrep tub ,dah evah dluoc netram elbaffa eht smelborp tahw enigami etiuq t’ndluoc gnasT
.dloc eht fo kcis elttil a gnitteg m’I ?edisni klat ew dluoC“
,yltnatropmi erom tub ,enola kaerb samtsirhC ro ihzgnoD dneps ot dah regnol on eH
taht wonk ,ecaf yam uoy elbuort revetahW
samtsirhC dneps t’ndluohs uoy taht gnikniht saw I .gnasT ,wonk uoY“
,wap a htiw ffo flesmih dekorts eh os ,emac tey t’ndah tub
.rae sih ot txen lworg s’naibaF emac ”.tac yddup ,os yas uoy fI“
RETNIW NI DNEIRF A“
!evael ot uoy deksa evah t’ndluohs I
.dnim sih ni gnorw s’tahw gnirebmemer ylneddus ,deksa gnasT
.taht teg I ,yag er’uoy em dlot uoy ,gnasT“
”.retteb ti gnikam ot s’ereH ?tac
.taht tsuj er’yeht ,llew ;spukooh rof sA“
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
.egdirf s’moor nommoc eht sdrawot deklaw eh sa
.lassimsid htiw tem neeb dah
”.no sehtolc ym teg tsuj em teL .thgirla ,mrE“
,mrod sih fo tuo teg ot dlot kcab sruoh owt ton d’eh mohw ekiM raeD
,ekiM sa rellac eht dewohs DI rellaC eht sa
;tsuj s’tI .erac od I tub
.dloc eht ni yrassecen naht regnol yna tiaw ot ekiM gnitnaw ton
”.ereh gnihtemos gnissim m’I smees tI
.ecneirepxe taht fo emos no pat ot dediced eh os
,kcen s’naibaF no skcil latnemirepxe wef a evag eH
dna efil sih ni niap esnetni na hcus tlef reven dah gnasT
,detnap eh sa devaeh dna
.pruls kcils a htiw mih otni kcab dils naibaF
,yaw emos ni ytisrevinu eht ni tnemllorne
erutuf retteb a ot gnitsaot
.moor ym ni od ot ffuts emos flesym tog I tub ,lla dna yot kcuf a sa nuf er’uoy ,tik kooL“
.denaorg gnasT sa gniwardhtiw ylkciuq
,rood eht ta mih deteerg tnecca na htiw raugaj eguh A
.stnetnoc toh-llits eht fo htaerb peed a gnikat
”.enif s’ti ,ti teg I ,haeY“
.pirg thgit s’naibaF morf desaeler eb ot dna
,rebmuls pmil sti morf gninekawaer kcid nwo sih leef dluoc eH
,elzzum citsaisuhtne s’naibaF ni
.hguone saw taht dna ,derac ekiM ,won roF
.pu-neercs ti gninrut
.evael ot mih gnillet s’naibaF
.ylitsah dias gnasT ”.thgir ,sey ,hO“
.deffuh naibaF ”.sey ,kcuf ,hO“
”.dellac I yhw s’tahT
?gniht a hcus od dluow esle ohW
,erom ecno gnasT otni sregnif debul sih dils eH
,kcoc sih hguorht dessap muc fo nmuloc retfa
.sbrab eht fo gnibbur eht leef llits dluoc eh ,smodnoc enilef detacided htiw nevE
.esirprus ni gnikrej gnasT
”.uoy nraw t’ndid I yas t’noD
.os od ot deliaf dna deirt selggirw sih sa neve
flesmih fo tnedifnoc erom dna reippah raf neeb evah dluow eh nehw
dilef rellams eht
.regnol elihw a rof tnelis tpek gnasT ”.yakO“
.nwod kcab eil mih edam tsehc sih no hsup mrif a tub ,gniod saw naibaF tahw ees retteb ot
.mih tuoba derac taht ylimaf a ot emoh kcab gnidaeh erofeb
.tlep nwo sih evas
”,uoy htiw emit dneps ot gnitnaw ym rof nosaer eht t’nsi yag gnieb tub ,gnasT ,tnioppasid ot yrroS“
”.gnol rof ton s’ti fi neve ,setatS eht ni tfel ev’I emit revetahw yojne ot tnaw I“
,drawrof delzzun naibaF sa afos eht otno kcab gnispalloc
?uoy teg I nac tahW“
.kcol cinortcele eht fo peeb eht yb dewollof
.os rof afos eht no desserp gnieb morf tsehc sih no sseneros dna gnihca eht leef dluoc eh ydaerla dna
t’nsaw ereht gniredisnoc taerg ytterp saw taht dna ,dekcuf eh ohw ro
,tsoh sih drager ot denrut tac drapoel ehT
,ylthgils daeh sih gnitliT
?dneirf a gnidnif sa kniht emas eht si pu gnikooh kniht ot diputs os neeb evah eh dluoc woH  .ssel on ,”yot kcuf“ a
.kcuf ot kniwt a rof saw
!yrros m’I ,ekiM“
,redluohs s’netram eht otni debbos eh sa tsaf dna drah gnimoc sdrow eht ,erac t’ndid gnasT tub
.tniop eht ot thgiarts dna tceriD“
.tlenk eh sa derrup naibaF
.neht yb dellecnac t’nsaw noitacude sih gnimussA
.elzzun-dim ni deppots
.edaced tsal eht ecnis degnahcnu snoihsuc rieht evah ot dekool taht safos htiw
”.dias uoy tahw ta desirprus ytterp saw I ,llew
”.ot ton nosaer doog a fo kniht t’naC .sey yas nac uoY“
,mih ot klat ot enoyna ,enoemos rof etarepsed os saw eh tub
,mih ot resolc tac drapoel eht dleh eH
.denettalf srae s’ekiM
,deraor eh neht dnA
,klat ssel snaem ti
.oot flesmih rof gum a teg dluohs eh
?ees uoy tahw ekiL“
”retniW ni dneirF A“
.afos eht no sedis rieht no yal htob yeht taht hcus gninrut
edisni tog yllanif eh nehw dnA
.deneppah dah taht gnihtyreve gnissecorp dnim sih
hcum os em etah yeht rehtehw wonk t’nod I dna yag m’I stnerap ym dlot I taht
.esle eno on saw ereht nehw
.deddon gnasT hcihw ot
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tcaer ot desirprus oot raf saw gnasT
.edisni devil ohw elpoep eht fo retcarahc eht saw derettam tahw dna
?taht ekil doom eht niur ot evah uoy oD .tik
.meht fo ylroop kniht t’ndid srehto taht os ,meht tuoba tnelis tpek elpoep taht hguone gnissarrabme netfo erew yehT
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a ,floWisakiM yb
.erutuf eht rof epoh emos dleh gnitseggus saw ekiM tahw
,decaf eh smelborp eht dnatsrednu dluow ohw enoemos dnif ot etarepsed
dah tac drapoel eht maerd dna hsiw neddih yreve
,noitome pu-tnep yreve gnixaoc elzzum dna eugnot sih
.ecalp ruo ta noitarbelec ihzgnoD a od neve nac eW
.siht lla tuoba thguoht eh sa
,gnasT rof dna ,puc eht gnipruls ekiM yb ylno detautcnup
mih detpecca ohw enoemos dah eh sa gnol sa
,esacriats nedoow eht nwod ylwols yaw sih edam gnasT
,draeh eb dluoc gnidliub eht ssorca gniwolb edistuo dniw eht ylnO
tuoba klat ssalc ro mrod eht neve ton ,xes sa nekopsnu
,won od ot tahw aedi on dah gnasT
yddup elttil truh I did
,dluow dneirf doog yna tahw od ot gniyrt ekiM etipsed dnA
”,gnasT ,reilrae tuoba yrros m’I ,yeH“
,mih dniheb tuhs rood eht
.ti ni taews yksum fo etsat tniaf a gnitceted
.ekiM dias ”.ereht neeb ev’I
.pit sih ffo detpure muc fo epor a sa gnitnurg
.s0591 eht ni tliub saw ti nehw kcab ytisrevinu eht htiw emac taht kcirb dlo eht fo llits saw flesti gnidliub eht tub
eno siht piks nac uoy
.edis sih yb smra s’gnasT gninnip swap eguh sih
,etuc ,yas ot derad gnasT dna ,tsenrae os
”?taht dnatsrednu uoy oD
.ti dehcaer tac drapoel eht sa noos sa denepo rood ehT