,hcuoc eht ni rethgiarts pu tas eh dna
noitasrevnoc a pu dliub ot emit deriuqer esoht tuB
elif dnah a htiw swalc rieht gnineprahs stac ohcysp eht ot dessergorp dah eivom ehT
.ffo enoyna tup t’ndluow taht depoh eh hguoht
,flaheb sih no snac owt rehtona thguob dah orb sih
.mih detcatnoc eciffo nimda eht erofeb emit fo rettam a eb ylbaborp dluow ti hguoht
.ylimaf yttihs a ,esac siht nI
revol ro dneirf yeht eb
esle eno on dah dna ,derob saw ekiM esuaceB
.nepo ti gniknay ,rood mrod eht sdrawot deklats gnasT
.ssecorp eht hguorht og ot sah enoyreve ,noS“
.eudrevo gnol saw taht gnihtemos
.ton ro tnaem-llew ,ecnerefretni latnerap fo hguone dah
enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
:efiLypp4H >...gnipyT< yb dewollof
.tsaf dna drah ni gnimoc shtaerb sih
,no tnuoc ot luos a ton dah nuJ iaH gnasT ,eH
demees syawla eH
,serutcel ni kcab dial os
.thgif a fo trats eht ta flesmih etaticapacni ot aedi doog a ti thguoht reven
,raeY weN ranuL eht ot ylno dnoces ecnatropmi sti htiw ,samtsirhC ot ti fo snosirapmoc edam evah emos—
,meht gniteem erofeb enoemos htiw tsurt dna
.liat sih otno gnillaf
.depyt eh ,lleH sa gniroB
.yawyna selbuort sih ffo dnim sih ekat ot gnihtemos deen dluow gnasT
.rehtegot moor ot erew yeht sraey eerht txen eht rof mih etah ot enoyreve rof etupsid eno saw ekat dluow ti lla
,dnuora t’nerew yeht taht woN
nemar no gnitsisbus
.dehtaehsnu swalc sih htiw thgirpu gnignirps ,niradnam ni desruc eH
.scimonocE gnahZ ekiM
.ekiM ta ylluferac dekool gnasT
,taht did eh revenehw etuc os dekool eH
RETNIW NI DNEIRF A“
.kcohs ni afos sih fo edis eht ffo llef ekiM dna
;enohprekaeps no sllac sih ot denetsil syawla stnerap siH
,wap rehto eht no ,gnasT
.meht tuoba klat ot tnaw t’nod I ?ekiM ,tahw wonk uoY“ ?ot klat ot
.semit fo elpuoc a ot nekops ylno d’eh
,dediova erew ”htaeD“ ro ”lleH“ fo tnelaviuqe eht ni sdrow ,emoh kcaB
tcaxe eb ot rebmeceD 22—
.dab detsat won etsat railimaf eht tub ,deppis dna
,ytisrevinu saesrevo na otni detpecca tog eh nehW
”,tik a saw I nehw kcab bud niradnam eht was I .no s’tahw s’tI“
,hcihw ,tac drapoel a sa mih dezingocer ynam
,yltnecer enohp sih ot yaw rieht edam dah segassem nedal-evitelpxe owT
.thguohtretfa na sa dedda tac drapoel eht
,nmaD .ton ro dneirf
,retupmoc sih no pu dellac eh nrop revetahw ot ffo gnikcaj ylekil erom ro gniyduts yad sih fo tsom tneps ohw renol rehtona tsuj saw eh demussa ylekil d’yehT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
stac citohcysp owt tsniaga emoh yrtnuoc dnuorgrednu sih dnefed ot decrof esuomrod gnuoy a tuoba eivom a
,sepirts krad dna etihw htiw dekram daeh sih htiW
”.neht ,eb ot tuo denrut ti noitavoner tihs fo eceip A“ .demrifnoc ekiM
”?deirram gnitteg uoy er’nehW“
revihs ot dah won eh
.ton ro cilbup ni derebmuntuo
,mih pleh t’ndluow siht
P: ?mrod ruoy ta llitS ?ta uoy erehW
”?thgirla ,tuo ti krow nac ew dna ,si ti tahw em llet tsuJ“
,enola syadiloh eht fo tser eht dna
”.sraey eerht tsal eht rof ebyaM ?swonk ohW
”?yako ylimaf ruoy…tiiiihS“
.egnuol eht deretne yeht sa dehgual ekiM
s’gnasT .deralced ylduorp netram ehT ”!ruf eht nI“
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
,deneppah taht gnihtyreve rof taht mih gnidnimer
,rehtorb evissimsid sih htiw laed ot gnivah morf edisA
.mih tuoba togrof ylimaf sih nehw
,htuom sih fo tuo etsat eht hsaw ot reeb klim fo nac a nepo dekcarc eH
,ti tuhs ot edam eh
.kaerb samtsirhC eht fo tnuocca no dluow htnom rehtona tey tbuod on dah gnasT dna
×.× .rehtie emoh kcab teg ot hsur a ni mees t’nod uoY ?pu s’tahW
.ffo rednif noitacol rieht nrut t’ndid ohw esoht tsael ta ro
.nuf ym niur ot gnola semoc eninac citohcysp on ,yllufepoH“
.rehtorb a rof gaf a evah naht
.mrots dliw a gnihsal liat sih
fo eman eht yb tnuocca na was gnasT
?taht rof mih emalb yllaer eh dluoc tub ,elohssa reggib neve na won saw gneS iaH
s’gnasT fo enoN .eulav s’tekcit eht fo %05 eviecer ot
.ot etaler dluoc eh enoemos s’ereht fi ees neve spahrep
mra sih rednu seirecorg sih dehctih gnasT
,”ecnaraeppA tfahS/htaehS“ dna ”sgnikaM tleP“ gnidulcni
dlrow nredom ehT
saw ekiM .esolc yletomer enoyna evah neve t’ndid eh ,saw hturt
”,emeht s’eivom eht fo etisoppo sthguoht yppah kniht dna
”!’yag‘ yas nac uoy naht retsaf uoy ekamhctam ll’I ,em pleh sdoG eht ro ,srotsecna ruoy yb thgir od retteb uoy ,noS“
.tnew dna emac loohcS hgiH retfa ot ekops eh iepiaT ni sdneirf doohdlihc yna evah neve t’ndid gnasT
,elbissop erehw dediova saw 4 rebmun eht nevE
seitieD ylnevaeH eht ot gniyarp
.enohp sih rof gnihcaer
segassem tnes ohw eno eht saw gneS iaH fi rednow mih dah gnisarhp fo rennam eht tub
nwonk flesti ekam ot tnemugra nwolb-lluf a rof saw dedeen eh gniht tsal ehT
.gnissim saw gnihtemos tlef tey
:traehylenoL .ylper kciuq a tuo debmuht gnasT
.sreylf tuo dnah sevitatneserper TBGL lacol eht fo eno gniees retfa yllaicepse
.erofeb enohp eht no mih detcatnoc reven
.yug eht ot tuo egassem a epyt ot egaruoc eht rehtag ot etunim a koot gnasT
.emos meht dereffo ylkeem dna
fo strap 2 fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,noitacude ytisrevinu sih dellecnac tey t’ndah yehT
.nottub mocretni eht desserp dna
.enutrofsim ro kcul dab gnirb ot deveileb s’ti sa
,sraey 12 ot esolc rof
.rehtorb sih fo mih dnimer t’ndid tsael ta dna
.yraunaJ ni demuser loohcs llit
.t’nsaw eh fi neve gnasT ot noitnetta gniyap eb t’ndluow eh dna ,thgiarts
.rof hsikcep tlef eh gnihtyna teg ot steerts dloc eht klawer ot niap a eb dluow ti gnirugif
,hcamots sih ni nwonk flesti edam tonk A
,smetsys gniman naisA ynam htiw esac eht si sA
ro ytisrevinu otni tog rethguad dna nos esohw fo edis eht sdrawot dednet
.ereh revo nauygnat yttihs sa ffo dessap tahw dna
.dnuof eb dluoc nauygnat on
.ydaerla esruocer fo euneva rehtona hguorht og dluoc eh
fo strap 2# fo 1# eht eht saw sihT
.aM ,uoy rof swen emos s’ereh ,lleW“
,dedulcni setamssalc ,wenk yeht enoyna ot derrefer enoyreve
”?samtsirhC rof emoh gninruter er’uoy taht yas uoy t’ndiD“
,slauxesomoh htiw od ot gnihtyna evah ot gnitnaw ton tuoba lacov ytterp neeb dah gneS iaH
# .ylenol erom tlef reven dah gnasT
,deraen kaerb samtsirhC eht sa dnA
,deliob gnieb retfa devres yllanoitidart si nauygnaT
”.siht ,eivom fo eciohc eciN“
.iepiaT dettod taht steerts doof eht fo eno ni
,sehsub evas eno on gnieeS
degassem ro dellac evah dluoc eh sdneirf fo kcal on dah netram ehT
.ytirailimaf seiceps emos eb tsael ta dluow ereht os
,sOS rieht ro ylimaf ot emoh tnew did ohw esohT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,floWisakiM yb
.thgieh rieht sretrauq-eerht ymene nommoc a saw ti fi neve
.retneC ytiC eht ni detautis erew meht fo tsom taht gniton
.s’gnasT ekil tsuj snosaer rof emoh nruter t’ndluoc spahrep rO
,enola hcum ytterp mih tfel yehT
snoitces lareves erew erehT
enola saw gnasT ,niveK ekiL
.gnihtyna deirt enoyna fi ti tuhs dna tuo daeh sih kcits
.nosaer revetahw rof eno teg ot gniyrt saw rengierof a taht egnarts kool dluow ti sediseB
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,setatS eht rof tfel eh ecnis reve rehtorb sih fo dir eb ot dalg naht erom saw gnasT
.lamron ot kcab teg ot gnihtaerb sih rof setunim 51 koot ti dna ,llac eht tuc gnasT
”!skniht ylimaf ym tahw erac I od rehtien dnA“ .gnasT delrans
.ythguanK dna rdnirG ,redniT dedulcni esehT
.emosenol sih no tneduts ngierof a saw eh sseug t’ndluow remocwen eht taht os ”oy“ eht dedda eH ”?ti si ohw ,oY“
hsarcetag dluoc yeht thguoht ohw
,hcamots s’tac drapoel eht fo tip eht morf flesti daerps htmraw A
ti tfel d’eh erehw reeb sih pu dekcip tac drapoel ehT
,neht egarednu saw gnasT hguohT
.meht daer ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc gnasT tub ,segassem txet sseltnuoc
.taht fo esu ekam dluoc eh woh wenk gnasT dna
iepiaT ni emoh siH .gnihtemos ro esuoh mraw a ot emoh
,emoh kcab thgilf sih dellecnac gnasT
,taht no delttes eh sa tsuJ
,ecnelis htiw ecaf evas ro kcab txet dluohs eh fi gnirednoW
.thgiarts ruoh na naht erom ffo kcaj dluoc enoyna fi sa
.laem s’gnasT fo sniamer eht ta derats eH
.kcuf ot derreferp eh ohw naht rehtar saw eh ohw rof
,od ot gnihtyna fo kcal roF
.ragus dna sdees emases htiw dellif sllab ecir suounitulg
,elzzum sih denepo ekiM
.sOS rieht ro ylimaf ot emoh tnew osla
,esnopser on saw erehT
,erofeb slaem rof syug eht nioj ot mih deksa dah ekiM
,htiw nigeb ot meht htiw seussi nwo rieht dah ylbaborp yeht ,saw hturt eht tub
,elihw a rof emoh wen sih eb ot dekool tahw ot kcab klaw gnol eht yb dewollof
tac drapoel ngierof emos enola tel ,sppa gnigassem fo noitanibmoc yna hguorht
,revewoh ,supmac no srehto eerht tsael ta erew erehT
,lleH fo struoC neethgiE eht yb denmad eb d’eh taht
?yawyna ,raeh ot ereht saw tahw dnA
niatrecnu dekool noisserpxe siH
,mih erofeb eivom eht ot kcab seye sih werd eH
.loohcs hgih retfa krow gnidnif elbuort dah gneS iaH nehT
.gnitisiv eb dluoc ohw
.esolc os samtsirhC htiw stnuocca rieht gnikcehc eb neve ro enilno eb dluow enoyna detbuod tac drapoel ehT
,erom ecno pam eht ta gnikooL
;sppa dna setisbew gnitad tuoba wenk eH
.supmac no yrrac ot stneduts wolla t’ndid ytisrevinu sih ,yawyna dnA
,snoitseuq s’rerutcel eht rof rewsna na dah syawla tey
,”seitinutroppo erom“ evah dluow eh taht nosaer eht rof
,eno rekciht a yub dluohs eh fi niaga ecno gnirednow
esle enoemos fo sdneirf erew yeht sselnu mih dda dluoc esle eno on os etavirp ot tes syawla erew sgnittes sti hguoht
;srehto dnimer yltnatsnoc ot dah gnasT sa
.sgniht hcus tuoba kniht ot doom yna ni t’nsaw gnasT tub
”.neht llit tiaw ot evah ylno I os ,worromot rof dekoob si dnuohyerG eht rof tekcit yM“ .delkcuhc ekiM
,htiw railimaf erom elttil a s’eh gnihtemos ot lennahc VT eht egnahc ot meht llet ot egaruoc eht nommus reven dluoc gnasT
.gnisimorp dekool eman ehT
,ecalaP ylnevaeH eht fo sdoG
”,ekil uoy fi yats nac uoY
noitautis sih dnatsrednu dluow ohw elpoep wef eht nehw yllaicepsE
.egassem yna etorw ohw mih saw ti llet ytterp dluoc eno dna
dedaerd eht htiw gnola
.”ezoob“ ti llac emoS
,scimonocE dlroW gniyduts raey tsrif s’gnasT saw tI
.yas ot dengied yeht revetahw gniraeh naht retteb saw ecnarongi gniwonk ,sllac rieht erongi ot esohc eh tub
.dellorne eh sa noos sa nug a thguob eh
,lufetargnu mih kniht ot ypp4H gnitnaw toN
”.ylimaf eht htiw eb ot emoh gniylf erew uoy gniyas uoy draeh I
,gnigakcap draobdrac eht morf yawa resiewduB fo nac a desirp eH
.iepiaT ni kcab ylimaf sih gniees ot drawrof gnikool eb dluow eh
.niaga dlof eht ni kcab mih teg ot tseb rieht gniod stnerap sih saw ti derugif dna ,no noitcennoc atad elibom sih tpek syawla eH
,snoitome sih htiw smret ot gnimoc lauxesomoh a gnizicartso tuoba eciwt kniht t’ndluow ohw elpoep fo hguonE
.oga retsemes a tsomla deliaf dna deirt ydaerla yeht nehw yllaicepse
.emoh morf ton yletinifed tsom erew
,detrats retsemes eht ecnis nekorb neeb dah dne rieht no metsys mocretni eht derebmemer neht eH
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.gnirps fo gnimoc eht sdlareh hcihw
.eciohc a fo hcum evah t’nod I“
.reciffo ytiruces s’ytisrevinu eht dna ffats krow wef a rof evas
,lleW .ylper eht emac
mih fo tnorf ni t’nsaw ekiM taht woN
.0X reeb dna skcans emos rof gnippohS
.ylper t’ndid ekiM
,dnuora erew setammrod rehto eht revenehW
,egassem margeleT eht ta derats gnasT
,gnahZ ekiM detnuoc eh sselnu
,flesmih ot VT dna
.desu reven tub enohp sih ni dellatsni dah eh sppa rehto eht hguorht deppilf gnasT
,tsael eht yas ot sgabmucs fo tseilwol eht gnieb dna
,yawyna retsaf evom t’ndluow eueuq eht dna
,snoitome s’elpoep rehto gnidaer seitluciffid dah syawla gnasT
,ihzgnoD evresbo did yeht
,rehto tnacifingis rieht rof tnaem gnihtemos rof gnikool ereht erew meht fo ynam woh derednow gnasT
,ereht nees d’eh sledom elam gnikool-doog eht fo esuaceb
gnizilaer erofeb thgir
.emit eud ni ti xif ll’yeht detsisni dah ecnanetniaM hguoht
# ): ereht uoy eeS !sknahT
,seiceps ralimis a fo erew yeht fi neve
”.rehtorb a fo krej ym s’oS .enif er’yehT“
dlo dna wen stneduts eht lla
mrod eht ni enola gnieB
.enohp eht no deppans gnasT
,siht ekil gnihtyna enod gnivah ton etipseD .depyt gnasT
.snac owt htiw 81 gnimoceb sih etarbelec ot detnaw gneS iaH dna
.won yb hguone dah gnasT tub
:traehylenoL .eb ot smees raugaj eht yug tnedifnoc A
esuom eht eusrup ot denimreted deniamer sralgrub owt eht ,taht etipseD
,stsihdduB erew ylimaf sih dna gnasT
.reeb fo kcap-xis a saw swap sih fo eno ni dna
,tnemevom TBGL evissergorp a sah iepiaT
.meht tuoba ylimaf rieht llet ot elba gnieb ton tey
,efil sih fo tsom enola neeb d’eH
.enohp ’stnerap sih hguorht
?ereh neve uoy era yhw
,seirtnuoC dlroW dr3 ni seimonocE lamrofnI no tcejorp taht morf edisa tub
,ffuts lanosrep dna krowloohcs tuoba htob
,desufer dah gnasT
.lavitseF ecitsloS retniW eht
.rehto eht morf mih gnitarapes naeco na tuoba yrrow ot evah t’ndid netram eht dna
.2 level ,etaG s’nedlE ni s’mrod yM
”?enola gniknird erew uoy ,tahW“
,tuo kcuf eht teg ot mih llet ot evah t’ndid ylniatrec eh dna
,meht deilppa dna sgnittes evitcirtser esoht lla dekcehcnu gnasT
,swap sih ni ecaf sih tup gnasT
,revewoh ,no sthgil rieht fo emos dah noitaicossa TBGL s’ytisrevinu ehT
,emoh nruter regnol on dluoc eH
.detrats retsemes eht ecnis nwod s’mocretnI“
.gnihtemos ro noisivelet weiv-rep-yap sa hcus
,semit fo elpuoc a ekiM ot nekops d’eh ,eruS
,gniknird thgin sih dneps ot dib a ni sevlehs rouqil eht gnittih fo daetsnI
,wef tceles a rof tpecxE
,kooL“ .deppans gnasT
.raf taht tog neve sgniht gnimussa
.htiw nigeb ot smret gniklat no eb neve ro ,rehtegot seivom eht ot tuo og ton thgim yeht hguoht neve ,”sdneirf“ sa
noitaralced s’gneS iaH yb detautcnup ylkciuq saw ecnelis dennuts riehT
;reffo ot dah yeht tahw ees ot
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ti nepo ot ekam t’ndid tub kcap-
,sdneirf llac dluoc eh enoyna evah t’ndid eH
,no tnuoc ot rehto hcae dah yeht tsael ta
ydaer gnitteg eb ydaerla dluoc
?raf os yadiloh ruoy s’woH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”.kcab skeew thgilf ym dellecnac I .eromyna toN“
.syaw htob dekool dna rood eht denepo eH
eht tub ,meht tuoba ylimaf sih llet ot evah ton dna
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.detsaw yletulosba
,swap htob htiw ti nettalf ot tseb sih deirt eh dna
dnim sih deretne edistuo namnug demra na fo sthguoht ehT
,tlep dettops a yb deinapmocca
.enif gnola tog gnasT dna eh
.ssendnuor rieht fo tcepsa no ytinu dezilobmys dna
oga shtnom hcraes sih morf derebmemer eH
.egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no
,mih detseb dah wenk eh rehtorb elttil ehT
.tac nommoc ron drapoel rehtien saw
,hcihw fo gnikaepS“ .hcuoc eht otni nwod deppolf netram ehT
netram deltitne niatrec a fo
,snoitalubirt dna slairt rieht dnatsrednu ot
.syad eseht xilfteN ot noitpircsbus a evah ot demees enoyrevE
.mih detpecca llits stnerap sih ton ro rehtehw gnirednow ,emoh morf raf
.rerutcel ro AT a ylbaborp
!efil fo elcyc lluf eht fo trap s’tI
,weiv lluf ni nwohs erew sbrab sih taht os otohp eht ekater ot dah gnasT ecirhT
”.si traeh eht erehw s’ylimaF
:inU morf emoc dah ti taht gniretsiger erofeb
,eueuq eht ni saw eh setunim 03 txen eht roF
t’ndid ohw esoht elihw
,gnieb-llew sih tuoba gniksa meht dah llac ylkeew rehto yrevE
,mrof eht ta derats gnasT sa setunim esnet lareves saw tI
eht lla ot ti nevig gnieb lla ti fo taht ot seitinutroppo fo kcal sih demalb gneS iaH
.emac ht02 rebmeceD
slliks sih hcum os ton saw ti yas ot ydaer syawla saw dna ”mucs inu“
.serutcel fo edistuo enoyna teem ot tey dah eh tcaf eht etipsed ,tahT
.emoh kcab sllac raluger edam gnasT
.gnihtemos ro hcuoc eht no gnillihc ylekil saw eh taht hguone tsaf emac ylper s’ekiM
.nuJ iaH gnasT gnidulcni
.nwo sih no etarbelec tsael ta dluoc eh
.nwod srae sih htiw tuo edirts ekiM dah taht
,renaelc eugnot citsalp a htiw nwod ti deparcs eh sa tuo eugnot sih kcuts gnasT
taht os tsuj noitcelfer-fles cilohcnalem nwo sih
.did esenawiaT emos ekil samtsirhC etarbelec t’ndid yeht os
bulc etabed eht no saw ekiM
.dniheb tfel dah ekiM kcap-xis eht ni snac gniniamer eht deips tac drapoel ehT
.feirg ydoolb hcum os meht desuac d’ohw
.dlrow leurc dloc eht ot elbarenluv dna
.ssa eht ni mih etib ot kcab emoc edarg tihs a evah dna
.neercs eht ot yldetniop denrut gnasT
.esrow eht rof nrut a koot pihsnoitaler ’srehtorb owt eht
,raugaj a saw eh dnA
,”enilnO“ ot ”yawA“ morf degnahc sutats s’ypp4H nehT
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
,sdrawkcab dekrej gnasT dna
,htiw elbatrofmoc tlef uoy mohw elpoep era sdneirf ,gnasT oT
.elzzum sih ssorca nirg a
.emoh denruter tey t’ndah ohw esoht rof no tneve na dah yeht gnitseggus
dna aM .nwotemoh sih morf raf os gnieb etipsed
slanif s’retsemes siht no mih gnidarg eb dluoc ohw enoemos ot gnikaeps ekoj laer a eb d’tI
,reisub erew sdaor eht erehw
.ti tfel d’eh erehw nac reeb eht pu gnikcip ,deggurhs gnasT
1# traP ,floWisakiM yb
?yllaer ,rehto hcae wonk yeht did llew woh ,lla retfA
.neercs no eivom eht detacidni ekiM
.laeppa elttil yrev sdloh
,slavitsef eseht htob nI
.pu mih depleh ekiM sa
,saw gnasT ereh dnA
,ecivres yratilim ni emit sih dedulcni eh fi
.did gnasT margorp scimonoce emas eht deiduts ohw netram detaorht-wolley a
,smret loohcs eht gnirud naht detresed erom gnidliub eht htiw ,won nevE
,koobzzuF no mih dda ot pu gniueuq eb dluow sessalc morf wenk eh elpoep ekil ton s’tI
,ega nwo sih fo enoemos ot kaeps ot retteb eb thgim ti derugif gnasT
,loohcs ni llew ylevitaler did
.mret trohs eht ni tsael ta
.pleh ot gniyrt tsuj m’I .nuJ iaH ,no emoC“
,segatnavda sti dah
.htiw rehto hcae revo klat ot retteb eht lla
,slennahc tnereffid no erew swohs demeht-samtsirhC fo ytnelP
.no etaler ot tniop nommoc a evah yletinifed yeht
?thgir ,rood rieht ta thgir naht dnaherofeb detcejer eb ot retteb tuB
,cilbup ni gniht tnatropmi tsom eht si ylimaf syas enoyrevE
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
,enolA emoH gnidulcni
retniw gnirud gnillaF
.ereht enoyna ot klat ot ecnedifnoc eht evah t’ndid eh esuaceb ti llatsni ot tey evah tub
,setats eht ni desiar dna nrob saw ekiM
.enal tuo-kcehc tsaf eht ot
ylimaf sih htiw pu nworg d’eH
.meht tuoba erac ot eno on dah yeht esuaceb ylniam setaf rieht tuoba tihs a evig t’ndid yllaer taht dlrow A
taht os ,gnihtyna ,gnihtemos htiw ylper dluow ypp4H taht
”,ognil eht otni teg d’uoy nehw gnirednow saw I“
,tuo dehsub lla saw ruf s’gnasT
.gnasT mih dellac loohcs ni enoyreve hguoht
.gnidliub mrod a ni erehwemos detacol
,sdrow dna gnicnetnes sih yrav ot hguone evitaerc reven saw tac drapoel redlo ehT
,rood eht ni ssalg eht hguorhT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,gniknird saw gnasT reeb klim eht morf taht naht elbaeciton erom raf saw gnitaname lohocla dna spoh fo llems ehT
hguone dah gnasT ,lla fo tsal dnA
t’nseod aM .ht42 eht fo thgin eht no s’evE samtsirhC ,dekcehc I tsaL“
,ygolohtnA 01 GNAF eht ni
.ydaerla pu nethgil ,yeH
,enolA emoH hctaw si won thgir od ot tnaw I lla ,lleH
”.gniksa er’uoy tahw s’taht fi ,deirram gnitteg reven m’I ,aP ,aM“
,sdneirf fo egatrohs on dah dna
,sresu rdnirG ybraen rehto fo pam noitacol eht dekcehc eH
.”eid“ rof drow niradnam eht ekil dednuos ti sa
.noitavresbo gnitseretni na ot gnasT werd sihT
,neht retteb gnola tog gneS iaH rehtorb sih dna eH
erew yeht llit knurd d’yeht hcihw
emit rieht yawa elihw pleh ot enoemos dah yeht
,ni denioj neve rehtorb elohssa sih semitemoS
.gnir ot deen t’ndid dna sdrac ssecca nwo rieht dah yeht ;ffats gnisuoh eht ton yletinifeD
ihcom nehw emoh fo etsat a gnitteg yrt ot mih dessessop tahw gnirednow
.denibmoc snaol tneduts sih naht erom tsoc sllac ecnatsid gnol—
,mih erofeb deraeppa nworb dna wolley thgirb fo hsalf A ”!esirpruS“
swalc sih tcarter ylwols mih dah noisufnoc dna esirprus fo xim
detsisni neve dah stnerap siH
.ytilauxes sih tuoba wenk setammrod
”.nemow ton ,nem ekil I
.talf srae sih ,yrrow ni desaerc elzzum s’ekiM
.emoc ot denetaerht taht sraet eht kcab thguof gnasT dna
,tekramrepus eht fo sevlehs eht delwart gnasT
,yteixna ni gnihsal tiuq liat s’gnasT
?yas dluow regnarts modnar yna tahw gniyas tsuj eh t’nsaw
.emoh kcab edir nwo rieht gnihctac erofeb
,no tnuoc ot enoemos gnivah taht tlef tac drapoel ehT
,won enola yats dluow eh won dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.yltrevo snoitome sih sserpxe dluow yug siht naem osla dluow snocitome fo esu ehT
efil ni sseccus s’eno erehw nawiaT ni ralupop erew yeht
.gnar yrotimrod eht ot lleb eht
”.raey tsal tsuj revoekam a tog gnidliub siht yas sroines ehT .ti tbuod I“
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a ,floWisakiM yb
,secalphtrib ro snwotemoh rieht ot denruter dna ffuts rieht dekcap
.dehgual ekiM sa ruf mra sih gnikcil
.ezis tonk dna htgnel eugnot sa hcus sliated dinac erom eht no sisahpme htiw tahw
gnimoc ot desu oot saw ydob sih spahreP
.noitcefrep enilef ot dekorts eh kcid nwo sih fo eifles a koot eh hcihw fo
,nwo sih llac ot OS na dah eh dehsiw eH
,tcaf taht ekam depleh ylbaborp ti detarbelec ereh elpoep yna fi wef taht tcaf ehT
.emit eraps sih ni tsil tcatnoc sih hguorht gnippilf neeb tsuj d’eh spahrep os ,emit emas eht ta dah yeht kaerb yadiloh tsrif eht osla saw siht ,neht tuB
.pu dehsub lla ruf sih
eueuq gnikans eht denioj eh sa detarbiv enohp s’gnasT
mrod eht gnivah detarebil ylthgils tlef gnasT
.dneirfyob ro dneirflrig a dah uoy rehtehw ni detnuoc osla saw
.dedulcni sgnilbis yttihs
gnasT yrruc fo snoissime eht neve dnats t’ndluoc eson sih taht nevig tub ,tsael ta yarps reppep teg eh detsisni d’yehT
,kcab sraey ytriht revo emoc gnivah stnerap sih
eno siht piks nac uoy
.ylniatrecnu deksa eH ”?ekiM“
.gnitaeh mrod dessa-flah ni
dad sih ekil dednuos tahw morf raor a fo sgninnigeb eht draeh eh
,gnirehtag ihzgnoD yreve fo trap largetni na erew yehT
.yrtnuoc siht ot gnimoc erofeb daer d’eh seirots swen enilno esoht lla ot kcab thguoht eh sa
no tnuoc dluoc uoy elpoep
.gniht elohw eht ot detcaerrevo dah eh fi derednow gnasT
,gnola teg od reven srehtorb redlo dna regnuoy tub
”,mocretni eht htiw rood eht ta s’ohw ksa dluohs yllaer uoY“
nos rieht tpecca t’ndluow ohw
,tekcaj sih otni deldduh eH
,nialpxe ot htuom sih denepo gnasT
,ytisrevinu fo edistuo dna ni mih rof seciohc erom stol erew erehT
”retniW ni dneirF A“   :yojne esaelP
.tcaf taht pleh yltcaxe t’ndid srehto ot gnikaeps ni tnedifnoc dna evaus taht lla t’nsaw eh taht tcaf ehT
.snoitacilbuP tenalPruF yb dehsilbup
.srehto ot tuo uoy lles ton ot ton
,setatS eht ni ereH
,ereh yaw eht lla nwod kcap-
emoh s’esuomrod eht deredisnoc d’yeht retfa thgir
esruoc fo ,sllac ppastahW dna epykS yttops hguorht llA
”,yaw taht yats ot ti dnetni I dna ,rettam lanosrep a s’tI“
.hsrah ssel hcum os ,elbaraeb hcum os efil ekam dluow
”.nug a htiw rettun emos eb syawla dluoc I“ .detnemmoc ekiM
.no detnuoc evah dluoc eh elpoep ylno eht morf noitaicnuned dna elucidir fo sdrow eht ees ot raeb t’ndluoc eh dna
?ereh llits uoy era yhw nehT“
?gnihtemos ro mrod eht ni tuo gnignah uoy ,oY
,taht fo esuaceb dnA
.enoyna ees t’ndluoc gnasT
.taht tuoba eil ot deen yna t’nsaw ereht derugif gnasT .seY
.ssih gniyfsitas a htiw ti gninepo
.yag tuo denrut dah
,eugnot sih nwod diulf nedlog eht deruop eh sa dnA
mih llik renoos d’eh taht dna
.ot etaler nac eh enoemos dnif ot etaidemmi erom gnihtemos dedeen eh wenk gnasT
”.evael retteb d’uoy kniht I“
ffo lla ti pot ot dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ylkciuq rood eht nepo d’eh taht dediced eH
”!taht tuoba kniht uoy tahw erac t’nod yllaer I dna ,yag m’I“
”,enola smelborp rieht fo nedrub eht raeb ot evah reve dluohs eno oN
,rehto ro noitidnoc htlaeh emos fo esuaceb ecivres yratilim morf detpmexe saw eH
.mih wenk yllautca ohw
.ecneirepxe railimafnu dna laerrus tsom a saw
,sredurtni tac eht yb decaf seitluciffid eht etipseD
.ihcom elbavaworcim htiw esac eht eb ot t’nsaw siht taht smees ti tub
.ton ro meht detarbelec yeht rehtehw ,syadiloh samtsirhC eht devol ytisrevinU nwotowT ni enoyrevE  2# fo
.tnemom siht ta netram eht ot kaeps ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc gnasT tub ,ysetruoc nommoc a sa tsael ta
srebmem ylimaf elohssa fo hguone
.erahs ot gnilliw neeb evah tsum eh
.enoyreve rof ydaer ekoj a dah dna
,tahwemos mih denevilne sniarg detnemref fo xim eht fo gnits eht
noitpecnocerp eht evah ot demees osla yeht tub
yclamron fo esnes a evag ti
,ekiM ot snac esoht nruter dluohs ylbaborp yllaer eH
,deliob saw ti sa detargetnisid dah ihcom ehT
setats eht ni seiduts sih eusrup ot mih degaruocne dah aP
,delbuort dednuos eh fI
.meht tog raey a 000,03$ tahw saw siht oS
,mih ot gniklat redisnoc reve dluow taht elpoep wef eht fo eno dezicartso osla d’eh tub
,daetsni ihcom elbavaworcim emos gnitteg rof delttes gnasT dna
,gnola nettog dah srehtorb eht nehw kcaB
.esrow raf noitautis eht ekam dna won thgir
.esuoh eht retne gnasT gnittel erofeb tsrif peelsa erew aP dna aM rehtehw dekcehc dah gneS iaH
.rotcetorp neercs ssalg derepmet eht tsniaga eciwt gnippils walc dehtaehsnu sih
.emoh yllautca t’nsaw eh fi ylppa t’ndid selur eht derugif gnasT tuB
,yaw yna ni mih ot krej a neeb t’ndah ekiM tuB
,ecneidua thgiarts a sdrawot detneiro erom demees redniT taht
,61 saw eh nehw kcab saw knurd d’eh emit tsrif ehT
.snocitome eseht lla evol attog s’ekiM
esle enoemos htiw ecnelis elbatrofmocnu na ni noonretfa eht gnidneps hguohtla
,hcuoc moor nommoc eht ot revo dedaeh dna
sgnirehtag ylimaf ta snoitasrevnoc
.tuo devom dah gneS iaH dnif ot emit txen iepiaT ot nruter dluow eh gnipoh
,semit lamron ni dna
samtsirhC dna ihzgnoD dneps ot demood
.emoh rof evael ot
?mocretni eht ta em rof ksa tsuJ
.erus rof s’taht ,taeh rof dekcal reven
,emoh ta ihzgnoD etarbelec t’ndluoc eh fi taht gnirugif
gniteem TBGL a no ni gnippord deredisnoc d’eH
,nauygnat rof noitces yranoitcefnoc eht ni dekool eh
,dah reve eh naht redrah rood eht demmals gnasT
,niradnam hcum kaeps t’ndid eh hguoht dna
”retniW nI dneirF A“
.esu dluoc eh senil gninepo noitasrevnoc tseb eht no elcitra na daer ro oediv ebutuoY a hctaw ot emit dah eh kniht t’ndid gnasT
.gnasT sdrawot ylwols deklaw eh sa
.loohcs ni ykcul nettog gnivah gnasT sa
?htiw nigeb ot ezeerb eht gnitoohs neve ekiM dna eh erew yhW
,ecivres yratilim yroslupmoc
.drac ssecca sih htiw rood s’mrod sih denepo gnasT
,yawllah eht fo thgil mid eht ni neve tuo doots sredluohs sih no ruf wolley ehT
,yag saw eh ekiM llet ot evah t’ndid eH
.yawllah eht hguorht mih wollof ot netram eht devaw gnasT
:efiLypp4H .emit eht fo hcum emosenol sih no gnieb morf neeb evah dluoc siht tub
.dedworc sklawedis eht dna
.od ot demees reven ti hcihw ,tuo worg ot taoc retniw sih rof tiaw ro
deraeppa ylremrof sah ”RETNIW NI DNEIRF A“
.gnihtemos ro ynapmoc rof etarepsed saw eh ekil tisiv a yap ot aedi taerg a kniht t’ndid eh
!dnuora gnah ot esle erehwon ,peY
,mocretni eht ot yllautceffeni dias eh ”,ereht ni gnaH“
,DI rellac eht kcehc ot togrof eh dna gnar enohp eht nehw ,retal sthgin owT
?uoy rof ti fo erac ekat em tel dna pu emoc uoy tuoba woh ,kooL
,seninac sdrawot erom detegrat erom demees ythguanK dna
,eltsirb ot gnitrats saw ruf kcen s’netram ehT ”.gnasT ,evoba doG“
xis eht thguorb dah ekiM fi ,sediseB
.emitnoon ta ekowa eh emit tsrif eht saw tI
mih tnes dah stnerap ehT
”...lla eb tsum siht taht teg I ,gnasT“
.gnippohs yrecorg emos od ot llam eht ot dedaeh tac drapoel eht
”,neht erofeb elttil a pu nrut I sa gnol sa dnim
,pu dellif eh taht sliated lanosrep sih gnidrager
.noitseuq nekopsnu na fo elddim eht ni ro kcohs ni rehtehw
,meht htiw thgif a detrats evah thgim gneS iaH
,afos eht morf pu gnarps eH
,kcolb ffats eht ni saw enO
aP dna aM denrael yletaidemmi gnasT
,wap no evah dluoc eh hsac eht lla gnideeN
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.suolaej gneS iaH edam siht dna
”.enog si esle enoyrevE
.enohp eht deppord dna
.sdneirf srekrowoc rieht llac dluoc eno sa hcum sa ,sdneirf gnieb sa detnuoc yldrah taht tub
,lla retfa tnuocca na pu tes ot mih rof emit s’ti taht derugif gnasT
,emit sih htiw od ot retteb gnihton dah eh gnirugiF
.ylimaf yppah gib eno gnieb fo trap lla
,tuo smra sih dleh redurtni ehT
,rebmetpeS ni namhserf a sa noissimda sih ecniS
.rood niam eht ot deklaw dna
.dennalp s’tahw ees ot no VT eht gninrut
dah gnasT ,raen werd rebmeceD emit eht yB
.ti tuoba raeh ot tnaw t’nod uoY .detacilpmoc s’tI
,yawyna reeb klim detnemref oatgnisT fo snac owt dna spihc hsif
.ssim a ti evig ot gnasT desuac
.ti nopu nworf llits stsilanoitidart ynam hguoht
,kcab gnillac deirt stnerap siH .erus rof s’taht
.siht tuoba og ot woh aedi on d’eh nevig
,evots eht ta atsap gnikooc ta dnah sih gniyrt saw eh nehw deretne neve yeht ecnO
,dap a htiw neercs eht debmuht gnasT
,sllam eht fo srodirroc eht degnorht sreppohs etunim-tsaL
.egassem eht tnes eh retfa thgir flesmih dekcik gnasT
.htiw nigeb ot dnuorg nommoc emos dah yeht taht os
?htiw knird ro klat dluoc uoy mrod ruoy ni esle enoyna t’nsi ereht esuaceB
.ssap d’eh gnidiced erofeb eno delpmas dah gnasT dna ,gnillif naeb der sti htiw nworb retaw eht gninrut
.yaw siht eb ot dah ti naem t’nseod taht tub
.srevaelc htiw tropria eht ta gnitiaw naht rehtar
.enoemos laiceps taht rof gnihtemos laiceps taht rof gnikool
,llef eh erehw morf pu ylwols doots ekiM
,dnuora t’nsaw aP fI
”.erofeb emac taht srotsecna ruoy lla ekil tsuJ
.rood eht no nwonk flesti ekam ot ecnatsiser a rof ylno
,retnec ytic eht ot yaw sih edam tac drapoel ehT
,ti was gnasT sa tub
.netram eht htiw srettam lanosrep gnirahs eb dluohs eh rehtehw derednow tub
.taorht sih ni pu gnidliub rrup yratnulovni na
:efiLypp4H .saw ereh dnuora smoidi eht revetahw ro
.D: rof s’ppa siht tahw s’tahT
”?retteb yna wonk t’nseod ohw rengierof a m’I esuaceb tsuj ,ereh krow sgniht woh wonk t’nod I kniht uoY
?tahw ro rollesnuoc lanoisseforp a yug siht saw
.remrof eht rof delttes dna
,hcnul ro eivom a rof tuo gniog otni mih klat ot deliaf raf os dah gnasT dna
,luos yna fo dioved saw supmac ytisrevinu ehT
;taht tuoba noitseuq on ,ylimaf sih yb denwosid neeb d’eH
?seog pihsdneirf rof hcraes s’gnasT woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni
,esenihC lanoitidart tsom ekil tuB
.shtapohcysp eht dednuow gnivah spart deggir-yruj s’esuomrod eht niveK
.ton ro noitcetorp esu ot derebmemer eh rehtehw neve dna
,nuJ iaH yllautca saw eman tsrif s’gnasT
,tsom eht rdnirG dekil d’eH
,gneS iaH rehtorb redlo sih edulcni t’ndid sihT
,ylimaf eht ot kcab gniog t’nsaw eh yhw tuoba snoitseuq rewsna-ot-tluciffid gniksa
.dehctih teg ot seitinutroppo erom evah osla dluow eh taht
,tseuqer tsal eht ecnis dessap ydaerla dah htnom A
.mih erih ot regae t’nerew sboj ralloc-eulb neve tnaem osla siht tub
.ydobon saw taht ,SU eht ni dnA
efiLypp4H
.od ot tahw derednow ylfeirb gnasT dna
.tnereffid yna t’nerew
.gnikcik dna evila llits saw eh
,saw eh ohw rof mih tpecca dluow ohw ylimaf a dah llits eh taht gnidneterp retteb tlef tI
egde na no koot eciov s’gnasT ”.woN .evaeL“
xis sih morf nac a deppop ekiM
ereht dedaeh mih gnittops wenk eh enoemos fo laitnetop eht dna
.sgnikcip epir yltcefrep
,seldoon hsif nemar emos debbarg tub ,knard ylerar eH
,tnuocca koobzzuF a dah eH
,sevlehs eht no sgnireffo lanoitanretni ylevitaler eht etipseD
.dilef erew yeht nehw ssel neve
.eman tsrif sih fo egasu s’ekiM ta srae sih dekcilf gnasT
.hcuoc etisoppo eht no tas gnasT
,elop egrab a htiw mih kcahw ro hcuot ot tnaw t’ndluow nosrep enas yna yllacitcarp
.seltitbus hsilgnE htiw esenotnaC ni saw ti fi neve
hcuoc eht morf pu tog tac drapoel ehT
.nettog dah smelborp sih peed woh tsuj gnirednow
,taht lla dna tnatropmi os si ylimaf woh mih gnillet saw ekiM nehw ,won nevE
.hcnup eht ot mih netaeb gnivah srehto htiw
derednow eh sa doots srae s’gnasT
,emit sih dneps ot yaw rehto emos dnuof evah syawla dluoc dna
,Px niap a eb syawla lliw dna si ylimaF
secnereffid larutluc fo raef eht tuB