.yadot tfig taerg a em nevig ev'uoY
.eneleS dellac ma I
fo rekinom eht no nekat yltnecer evah I
reh dnuora decnad ehS
yalp dluoc stirips ylno taht semag terces reh thguat eaf ehT
.erusiel ym yojne neve ton nac I taht nedrub a hcus si tI !yletulosbA“ ”.emoserit yllufeow teg tsum tahT“
.rrup detnetnoc sih fo dnuos eht sdrawot gninnur emac sepahs
”!ti evig ot yppah ma I nehT“ ”.ynapmoc dah ev’I ecnis emit emos neeb sah tI
.esle ecalpemos no reh gnirrits dniw eht leef dluoc ehs ,erom s’tahW
,dehgual eneleS siht tA
,eciov reh htiw kaeps ot tseb reh deirt eneleS
.yks eht ni hgih llits si nuS noonretfa eht tub ,eurT“
dlihc gnilggig eht del dna
.sevael eht fo gnitfihs eht htiw sroloc degnahc taoc reh ,nar ehs sA
”?eman ruoy si ,llet yarp ,tahW
reivaeh tlef ehS
.ekal eht revo edis eht ot daeh reh gnulf neht
deerga resuoM ,yltnatculeR
,mih fo tnorf ni demrofer dah ehs ecnO
.ydob a fo noitpecrep reh fo tfel saw tahw dnuor depparw liat dna elzzuM
seye sih dnuora pu erew swap siH
tnecs eht dnif llahs I nehT“
”sevaeL fo gniltsuR eltneG A“   :yojne esaelP
.enO dlO eht fo stoor eht tuoba repmacs dna
.ekal eht fo retaw eht no doots god eht ,regnarts nevE
?tnereffid yna eb ehs dluohs yhw
.flesreh decudortni ehs sa ruf sih fo tuo sevael eht gnikcip ysub saw eH
.sselyoj saw god eht tub
.elttirb dna yrd erew ydob reh pu edam taht sevael ehT
”?wonk ot erac uoy od yhW“
,snoitcerid lla ni tuo deltsirb ruf sih
.ekal eht otni gniknis erofeb semit wef a deppiks
,reh ni peed deirub yromem a saw tI
.derevocsid tsuj dah ehs hturt taerg a etacidni ot fi sa
.kcohs ni depsag dna
!ahtibaT elttil si siht ,yhW“
reh tfil dluoc ezeerb nmutua oN
,teef reh ta smossolb etihw dna knip eht hguorht mrof reh delriws eneleS sA
"!desruc neeb evah I ,salA"
.retaw eht no deppiks sah enots eht semit eht tnuoc uoY“
.ecnis em dnif ot elba neeb t'nsah ylimaf yM
.raelc saw hcum taht ,god a fo taht saw epahs ehT .railucep etiuq
,sdneirf wen reh evael ot tnaw ton did ehS
”yrekaB“ daer ngis ehT
gnihtemos deciton ehs
.emas eht lla uoy teem ot ecin s’tI“
.ylraelc mih ees dluoc ehs
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
retal wob llams A
.stros fo gniraelc a otnu emac ehs litnu
ton oD  .deedni nmutuA doog yrev a saw tI
.gnittep fo sdohtem tcerroc eht fo erawa ton era yeht nehw od nerdlihc taht yaw eht ni resuoM tep ot nageb
”.desirprus eb dluow uoY“
”?seye enim ot tneserp etiuq era uoy tuB“
,enot sih ta nekat eb ot saw esneffo fI
niaga ecno saw ehS
,ruof ro eerht naht erom on fo tot a
,tneps dna detsuahxE
.revo reh yrrac dluow dniw eht taht
senots gnippiks ,yaw siht no deirrac yehT
.ni flesreh dnuof dah ehs tserof eht ezingocer ton did ehS
.ykcul saw ehs fi ,tsom ta nosaes A
eirever sih morf mih esuor ot demees eneleS ot txen tot eht gnieeS
”!neht llew sa tsuJ“
.ereh mih tcerid ot woh fo niatrecnu saw ehs tub
m’I dna ereh em deirrac dniw ehT
dlihc eht rof hcraes dluow ylimaf eht
.yrtnuoc eht otni tuo
,swap reh ni eno dloh ot degnol ehS
”?em fo riaf kaeps yeht oD“
.peelsa tsaf mih dnuof dna
ytineres elpmis eht nI
.roolf tserof eht no sevael dedracsid eht hguorht tpews
,daeh reh otni deppop ”nogard“ rof drow ehT
.elohw ni detinuer eb dna
.drazil egral a ekil etiuq dekool epahs eht dna
!deen uoy tahw tsuj wonk I“
”?revir ruoy siht sI“
.llew sa gniklat saw eh dna
,flesym eno dah ton ev’I“
,dias dna god dessertsid eht ot denrut ehS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.reh ot yldnik ekops eert eht
”.lli on kaeps yehT“
.retaw eht fo ecafrus eht no yltneg llef sevael reh dna
.yad nmutuA looc a no ylesolc yrev kool uoy dnA
.ti tsniaga fo daetsni ,ti htiw nar ehs os dnA
.ecaf rieht fo tnorf ni sehcnuah reh no tas ehs ,cilorf reh fo derit saw ehs nehW
rehto hcae gnisahc dna
”?ecnatniauqca ruoy evah I thgiM
daeh rieht koohs eert eht ,peels gnol rieht fo stceffe eht gnileef llitS
dna retaw eht revo tuo gnilias tnew ti
.maerd a morf gnikaw fi sa reh ot emac ti ,eman reH
dnuora denrut evah I taht yrekcirt rieht ni gnixev os era sdliw eseht dnA
.on daeh sih koohs god ehT
retaw eht ni mrof dluow taht selppir eht dnuora decnad eneleS
.srewolf suordnow eht ta erats ot tub pleh ton dluoc eneleS
.yag dna ,yletirps dna ,gninnuc era uoy fi dnA
detcurtsni eneleS sa did tub
,denialpxe eneleS litnu
”?sdaeh rehto ruoy era erehw tuB
,htuom reh ni skcor eht fo eno barg ot fi sa noitom a edam dna
.ylthgils wob ot esuap a koot eH
!wollef enif yad dooG“  .ylkcarc dna niht sa tuo emac netfo ti hguoht
tniap ot nwonk neeb osla s’eH
.klofeaf eht ot eman eurt ym gnivig tsurt t’nod I fi em esucxe ot evah ll’uoY“
”?uoy htiw thguorb uoy evah ohW
,ruf htgnel muidem ,mot a saw eH
.uoy no shgiew ti hguoht sa sdnuos tI
.nellaf ylhserf llits erew sevael eht erehw
.ti fo ezis eht saw deciton ehs gniht tsrif ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,yawa deirrac eb flesreh tel ehs erofeB
”.gnihtemos gnidraug eb ot kool uoy tub
.rehtegot tnemom rieht liops ot ton sa os
”.yaw eht su wohs dluoc seireaf eht spahreP
”.ylderussa uoy xaler lliw tI
.erom on tsol saw eh sa noitale ni
,nodrap ruoy gniggeB“
”.revir a fo ma I ,esnes a ni ,sey tuB
.rewsna eht htiw pu til seye sih erofeb ,elihw a thguoht dna nihc sih ot wap a tup resuoM
,wolley dna neerg erom eb dluow ti semitemoS
.yawa dehsaw ylkciuq sa tsuj dna
,daeh sih deddon god ehT
.wollof ot ylimaf eht rof sevael der thgirb fo liart bmurcdaerb a tfel ehs ,deklaw ehs sA
desufnoc erom demees ylno god ehT
eneleS fo eniltuo eht ot revo dekool god ehT
spag eht hguorht ylthgirb enohs thgilnus ehT
.dnim ot gnarps aedi na ,nehT
eneleS tahT .wonk tsum uoy rof ,renetsil eltneg ,yrc
rehto hcae tsap dednuob yehT
,skoob daeR-oT fo draoh sih morf gnidaer ton s’eh nehW
.eno elttil ,raef ton oD“
.eritne gniht tnereffid a saw taehw tnrub tuB
.sraey ni erusiel ym deyojne ev’I tsom eht saw tahT“
.ti fo noitcerid eht ni reh welb dniw eht ,yllufetarg dna
.nwo sih fo seirots emos etirw ot emit sekam eh
.dniw eht yb deirrac eb dluow sevael fo elip gnilriws a ,hguone noos dnA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.dnim on ti diap ehs hguohT
.fo reh dednimer ecaf eht tahw llet dluoc ehs
tserof eht dnuora dekool eneleS
,noitpecrep ruo dnoyeb ecalp
.nwot yna naht retteb hcum yrtnuoc eht wenk ehs ,lla retfA
.pu meht kcip dluoc eh sa tsaf sa senots gnippikS
erofeb xof a nees evah tsum uoy niatrec ma I ,tsej uoy yleruS“
,eybdoog tuohtiw tfel dna
”.kaerb ot drah era stibah lanoitapuccO
,raef ot gnihton ev’uoY
.taehw tnrub eht llems dluoc ehs
.ecafrus eht ot kcab taobefil rieht ma I
.sselmrof dna depahsnU
.uoy erussa I ecnedicnioc a tub
,hgual a dekrab eneleS
.nepo ylwols deknilb seye dlo sa gnilbmum a dna gnilbmurg a saw erehT .rits ot nigeb
.nik sih htiw mih etinuer ot
”.klat dluoc dessap I seert rehto eht fo enoN“
.edisni ylimaf ylevil a htiw
.yrc etarepsed a delwem dna kcab daeh sih werht resuoM ,siht tA
.nees gnieb morf em speek thgilnoom eht dna
ekal a fo egde eht raen epahs ddo na ssorca emac ehS
.gniht a leef dluow enon dna
.ekal eht ssorca reh retfa gnisahc saw eh ,gnol erofeb dna
,tcerroc saw sseug reh fI
!lufituaeb yletisiuqxe si egailof ruoy taht yas tsum I“  .delims dna
.eciton ton did eneleS
.edis eno ot daeh reh detlit dna desufnoc dekool eneleS ".niur
,mih hguorht dna pu nar ehs sA
,resolc emac ehs sA
dlihc eht ta resolc dekool resuoM
,lacitpeks dekool god ehT ”!yrt uoy woN“
”.ega ot tsol neeb sah egaugnal eht rof ,meht raeh tonnac uoY
.eiriarp eht fo edis eht gnola gniklaw erugif a was ehs
.knurt eht fo esab eht sdrawot yllufecrof erom sevael reh dehsup dniw eht litnu
.yats slatrom tub ,og dna emoc stiripS“
!ti enod ev'I !enO dlO"
.uoy erussa I ,kaeps nac yehT“
.emitthgin eht ni elbisivni tub thguan ma won dna esuom gnikool egnarts a etA .desruc ,eyA"  "?desruC"
”.dnoyeb dnal eht ot slatrom eht rof yrref eht stolip norahC
erofeb pan kciuq a rof htrae eht otni sevael reh gniltteS
.reh fo trap a emaceb yeht
,srewolfdliw fo hctap ytterp ylralucitrap a hguorht gninnur saw ehs sa ,yad enO
knurt eht no ecaf eht eciton ton did ehs taht
rednauqs ot ton erus ekaM
.mrof ylevol a si ti timda tsum I
"?eman ruoy tegrof ot uoy desuac ecnatsmucric yppahnu tahW" ".resuoM
.mih ot ylimaf sih dael dluoc ehS
.mraw mih peek ot teknalb a sa sevael reh fo hguone tfel ehs
.sevael fo elip a otni thgit pu delruc dna
,gnillihc dna eltneg ,dniw A
eert ydahs egral a fo
.nageb yrots ruo erehw saw ,ereh ylurT
.srewolf eht hguorht decnarp dna deppiks ehs sa sgel reh neewteb dna
.rehtona dna rehtona nehT
.niatnuom a naht repeed snur dna eci naht redloc si ereht retaw ehT“
ffo kaerb dluow yeht emos hguorht elffuhs dluow ehs nehw dna
.pu nekow dah ti nehw morf roolf s’tserof eht ot nellaf dah enO dlO eht morf smossolb eht fo emos taht ees dluoc dna
”?lla ta ylimaf ruoy fo rebmemer nac uoy gnihton ereht sI“
,resuoM nopu tsal ta emac ehs nehW
”.ytuaeb ruoy dlrow eht fo tser eht wohs dna ydob ym ni ti yrrac dluow I ,dluoc I fI
taht ot ffo deirrac saw tirips reh dna
kcalb dna nworb saw taoc eht ,sesac lla nI
pu gnimoc erofeb tnemom a rof derednop ehS
.sevael fo elip tseraen eht ni edih ot nar dna tuo deirc eneleS ,siht tA
,deyonna gnikool fo daetsnI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
eneleS ”!eneleS m’I
enO dlO eht ot denrut ehS
.yoj ni kcab dellup htuom rieht fo srenroc eht sa gnikcarc krab egnarO
”?noitapucco ruoy si ,neht ,tahW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dlihc tsegnuoy rieht litnu detiaw ehS
.dehgual god eht siht tA
”.yas ot ecalp ym ton s’ti tub ,htraE eht fo erew yeht nehw rebmemer ot llew meht od dluoW
.eneleS ot txen retaw eht no nwod tas tub dehgis god ehT
mrywkooB irikeneN yb
”?htaed dnoyeb ecaps eht htiw uoy era railimaf woH“
,ylniatrec tsom ,lamina na saw erugif ehT
.liart eht fo sedis eht ot esolc yats ot demees ti tub
.noitartsurf sih esnes dluoc eneleS dna
,stirips tserof fo syaw eht ni desrev saw eno fI
.noisacco no eleluku eht yalp dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.tnuoc ot rebmun a ynam oot
.esimrus dluoc ehs tahw morf tnetsisnoc tsom eht eb ot demees elgaeB
raed ytilibissopmi na ma I"
.smossolb etihw dna
.wohemos ffo tlef llits ti tub
,ssarg eiriarp eht hguorht dniw ym fo gnileef eht ot desu m’I
!uoy gniknaht eb dluohs I“
.skeew tsap eseht redloc nworg dah nosaes ehT
.krab nwod gnippird purys ot ralimissid ton rennam a ni ekops yeht dna
.yrt tsael ta em teL .resuoM
.ruf htiw ton hguoht ,yzzuF
,ehs saw dexifsnart oS
.erofeb nees dah ehs yna ekilnu saw tI
.kcen sih dnuora deit ralloc der thgirb a dah dna
enO dlO eht tsap nar ehs
”.enO dlO ,ssendnik eht yaper dluoc I hsiw I“ ".yadot
,eert a era uoY
.erofeb nees ton dah ehs nwot a ni flesreh dnuof dna
.lufetarg dekool yllautca mot eht
ssenedur eno flesreh dewolla ehS
?flesruoy llac uoy od tahW“
.eye dekan eht htiw deviecrep eb nac taht esoht fo taht dnoyeb smlaer era ereht tuB
”.god ediug s’norahC m’I
tnorf ni elzzum a dna dniheb liat A
”.em rof wen yleritne saw retaw eht gnola gninnur tub
.delims eert eht ni nogard ehT
.sedaH fo gnikniht er’uoY“
”.eneleS ,hguone tfig si ecneserp ruoY“
.moc.irikenen.www no
.uoy erussa I ,yleritne wollef tnereffiD
.lla ta elbuort oN“
.ereh nwod edispu worg ot demees seert ehT
.niur ym eb ot saw ti etsatretfa eht morf nwonk evah dluohS
”.tuo emoc yam uoY .mrah on naem I
.htuom sih ni kcor a pu dekcip dna
”!ni llaf ot loof emos gnitapicitna ekal siht ssorca tuo gnirats ma I won nevE
.emas eht lla wenk ehs eno tub
.nem latrom fo smlaer eht ni niaga ecno ereh saw nmutuA
.yrt ot erad ton od ohw esoht fo drow a si ytilibissopmI
.emit gnol a ni srennam nommoc htiw mih taert ot tsrif eht saw eneleS fi sa saw tI
.ydob reh fo sevael eht htiw gnitaolf dna gnixiM
.ssom fo siri na hguorht gninnur
.tsrif eht era uoy ,yrartnoc eht nO“ ”?I
”.em thguat seiriaf eht taht emag a uoy hcaet ot gniog m’I“
.tnorf tuo ngis a htiw gnidliub enots taerg a erofeb devirra ehs ,ti gniwolloF
.tros a fo ,sevitaler era yehT“
.drazil taerg a osla tub
erom ecno god eht ecaf ot denrut ehS
"!liat ym hsiws I nehw si ti ytterp woh kool hO
.dniw eht thgif dna yrt ot naht
”.eneleS ,uoy knahT
tuo dedaf ehs sA
.eneleS saw taht sevael fo duolc eht hguorht dna otni nar god eht sa
.trohs saw ereh emit reh taht
”.nialp em ees dluow yeht
,reh fo tnorf ni tac eht yllanif gniees ,ahtibaT
.em llet ot elba eb d’uoy gnipoh saw I“
.emas eht lla ffo reh deirrac dniw eht tub
.nalp suoinegni na htiw
.yks eht otni drawpu taolf dna
.yks eht ni meht evoba hgih saw noom eht litnu
”.retal uoy knis seirrow ruoy tel ot neht
dnarre s’loof retaerg on si ereht roF
detrats syawla tI
lipup retaw eulb fo tnerruc a gniwohS
”.eneleS uoy ot yad dooG“
.ssecorp eht ni sevael drawyaw reh fo emos gnihctac
.god eht sdrawot daeh reh dekcoc eneleS
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb ”sevaeL fo gniltsuR eltneG A“ saw sihT
netfO .niaga yawa dna
tserof eht ni tseggib eht ylisae saw tI
.egde sti ta gnidnats saw eh litnu ekal eht ssorca deklaw eH
”!knis meht tel ot dewolla er’uoY
.tnemeticxe reh niatnoc ton dluoc eneleS
.yllacitnarf daeh rieht denroda taht seniv eht gnippihw
.seirutnec rof ereh neeb evah tsum dna
kcor dekcuhc eh sa tnemredliweb dna
edart yb resuom a ma I“
.llew etiuq roolf s’tserof eht ees dluoc eneleS dna
.woem I drah woh rettam on em ees tonnac yeht dna
.gnikaw retfa noos os flesreh tuoba egdelwonk hcum os evah ot ecnatsmucric reeuq a saw tI
.reh hguorht gniwolb dniw eht tuohtiw rewols dna
.noinuer rieht fo thgis eht ta demraw saw traeh s’eneleS
.evorg siht otni lla emoclew I
”.ecnatniauqca ruoy ekam ot erusaelp a si ti dna
,ecalp gnidih reh morf ylwols tperc eneleS
,erusiel ta erew uoy dias uoY“ ”.ti morf raf ,oN“
.eilloc a eb dluoc ti tnemom txen eht ni tub
”?reviR eht fo uoy erA
.retnec eht ni eert depahs ylegnarts a ot pu reh gnidael nees eb dluoc edis rehtie no meht fo enil a dna tuo denniht seert ehT
,ria eht ta ffins ot eson reh pu dekcip ehs sa noos sa roF
.raey siht nevig saw ehs emit eht ta delims ehs
”?fo tnirpmi na sevael ruoy era ydob tahW
,seert eht neewteb yaw siht deklaw ehS
deirc resuoM .gnidlocs dna
yad lla sevael hguorht wolb dluow dniw ehT
,ni sllaf latrom a fI
.reh raen sgnidliub on was tub ,semit wef a esolc emoc dah ehs thguoht ehS
.wollef ddo siht teem ot devloser eneleS os dna
.pu edis-thgir saw taht tserof eritne eht ni eno ylno eht saw eert siht ,llits regnartS
”.nwot eht ni ylimaf ruoy htiw meht dnuof I
.sevael eht fo swolley dna sneerg eht tsdima
.yrt uoy litnu wonk ylurt reven llahs uoy ,eneleS"
llew sa wenk ehS
”.won neve sedaf yromem eht tub ecno ereht neeb evah thgim I gnileef a ev’I“ ,deilper tub
.emitgnirps fo nruter eht ecnis nees neeb ton dah noitarbelec reyag a ,ylurT
.noitnetta ta ylduorp doots god eht dna
”.knis reven lliw I dna
.ekal eht otni kcor retfa
toof eht ta nwod flesreh dial ehS
”?daed eht fo ekal eht otni gnivid ot enorp slatrom ynam os erA“
esirprus ni delims god ehT
.sevael fo gniltsur eht fo
!elbissop ton si ti kniht I"
dniw fo tsug gnorts a yb tfola deirrac saw ehs ,ecnahc yb ,nehT
,lworg wol a ni dias dna reh ta nwod dekool eH
.enO dlO ,uoy knahT“ ”.evorg
”?od uoy od tahw ,neht tuB .ees I ,hO“
.sdneirf wen gnikam fo htmraw eht ni dehsiler ehs dna
.revo yaw rieht no xytS revir eht ssorc meht pleh ot boj ym s’tI
.wena dlrow eht hguorht nur ot evila
.sevael ylno ,erofeb smossolb detfil ton ev'I"
epahs a ekat ot gnitrats saw ,gnignahc dna diulf hguoht ,won mrof ehT
”.noitcejbo on ev’I .dloh nac uoy sa ynam sa ekat ,snaem lla yB“
.niaga reh hguorht gnihsup dniw eht leef dluoc ehs tub ,yats ot detnaw ehS
.ekal eht fo elddim eht ni kcab sih no yal god eht
pu deksihw saw ehs
edahs a sa semoceb ruf ym thgin tA
.ti fo esuaceb taehw tnrub fo llems syawla dluow dna gnidliub enots a raen devil yehT“
”!lufsserts yllufdaerd eb tsum yeht erutsop ruoy ta kool ot tub
.ylthgit oot elttil a ezeerb eht ot gnulc eno litnU
”!meht ot kcab uoy gnirb dna
,tnemom a ti no kniht ot dah eneleS
knip lufituaeb htiw tub
.wed gninrom ylrae eht hguorht edisyrtnuoc eht gnola decar ti sa
,godllub a ylraelc saw ti yaw eno ecaf reh detlit ehs fI
.riapsed fo tif a ni liart eht fo edis eht tsniaga depmuls saw eh
,esirprus reh ot tuB
?resuoM evil yeht od erehW“
”.htolc gnilddaws ni ebab a sa reh nees tsal dah I
.eert eht fo knurt eht no gnitser ecaf a fo epahs eht tuo ekam dluoc ehs ,esab sti dnuora klaw ot hguone esolc saw ehs nehW
neht dna ereht devloser ehs dna
sevael fo detsisnoc no gniklaw saw ehs dnuorg ehT
,meht ta gnikool saw ehs taht woN
reh hguorht wolb dniw eht tel
.edurtni ot naem ton did I
.nwot eht morf yawa rehtraf reh del ehs sa reh fo thgis esol ot reven erus gnikaM
,pu sevlesmeht ekaw ot htrof dna kcab
.kcab yaw ym llacer ton nac I gnol os tsol neeb ev’I
.niatrec rof si taht ,dniW eht fo tirips eht tog ev’uoY“
”.ecnis tnecs eht dnif ot elba neeb ton ev’I
eneleS ot stnerruc ekil deirrac eciov siH
.yks eht ssorca tesnus a gnikaerts
!rebmemer ton od I“
"?erom keew a rof traeh ruoy ni epoh dloH
.enola yalp ot tfel saw
.dniw dna sevael gnilriws esoht ni xof a eb ot
.oot gnihcraes neeb dah rehtom reh ,lived ylS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,yletanni sgniht wonk ot slamina fo yaw eht saw tI
yrtnuoc eht ni tuo raf siht sevlesmeht dnuof ylerar scitsemoD
.yenruoj reh no stserof eht fo seireaf dna eaf eht htiw semag yalp dluow ehs
,ylimaf s’resuoM dnuof evah ot dalg saw eneleS
.knab sti gnola pu dekcats
tuons a fo erom saw ecaf ehT
,sevael htiw ton dellif saw yponac s’tI
?trap tseb eht dnA
”.uoy gnikaw rof yrros os reve
dlrow eht lla rof dekool evah dluow ti
.htaenrednu krab deppirts ylhserf fo
.ylbaredisnoc denethgirb eneleS siht ta dnA
.llew sa em ot suoiruc si mrof ruoy tub
,flesti htrae eht morf fi sa ,wol saw eciov riehT
.eneleS saw ti ,ecno ta wenk ehs dnA
reh dnuora ylf ot dekil yehT
.enimreted ton dluoc eneleS ,gnideerb ralucitrap eht fo tuB
"?elbanu m'I fi tahW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.nwonknu eht otni tuo dna
.doog rof pu uoy nevig d’I !eneleS“
.niaga dnuorg eht ot kcab pord dluow sevael eht erofeb dnoces a naht erom rof
.ecneh sraey 3 rof meht morf tsol neeb evah I
thgin ta hcraes ylno yehT
.nwod eid dluow dniw eht nehw dewols ylno ehS
liat reh esahc dna eert eht fo esab eht dnuora nur ot nageb ehS
,evitpecrep etiuQ“
.mrof ruoy htiw railimaf ton ma I tuB
”sevaeL fo gniltsuR eltneG A“
.eneleS ,uoy no gnimoceb tsom era smossolb yM"
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
,nus eht fo thgil eht ni hcraes dluow yeht ylno fI
.dnuorg eht ni ylmrif detnalp spot eert eht dna yks eht otni tuo gnidnetxe stoor eht htiW
.llems eht tuo hcraes ot dniw eht no ffo saw eneleS dna
"?yawa devom evah lliw yeht yleruS
”.llew reh dna uoy stiuS
seye s’resuoM ni ssendas eht ees dluoc eneleS
”?ereh ylenol uoy erA“
!surebreC eht htiw gniklat m’I“
.seirots setirw dna semag sekam taht nogard a si ohw
,ssot eltneg a htiW
”.erusiel ym gniyojne m’I
egnaro thgirb eht dewohs dna pu denepo
,emit doog a ta em thguac ev’uoY
.gnidne saw mlaer siht ni emit reh wenk eneleS ,flesreh ot ti timda ot hsiw ton did ehs hguohT
yponac ddo eht ni
,eneleS dellac ma I“
.tegrof t’nod esaelp ,nossel eht si siht roF .terger yrrac ro
.niaga gniworg saw ssensselepahs fo gnileef taht dnA
”.eriF htiw ylnepo detrovac yeht thguoht I tub ,snogard fo wonk I
.tirips tserof ,oot uoy ot yad dooG“
selbbep dna senots ynam dah taht ekal eht fo egde eht ot reh wollof ot mih rof denoitom ehS
.nerdlihc s’dniW eht fo eno ,hA“
.reh ot revo nar dna pu detlob eh sa
,taeb a gnissim tuohtiW ”.aedi on ev’uoY“
.emas eht lla derrup resuoM ,siht etipseD
.ees nac uoy tahw ta desirprus eb yam uoY
nwod dekool eneleS
htuom s’ecaf eht sa draeh eb dluoc gnikcarc eltneg A
.reh wolla dluow dniw eht fi erusnu saw tub
sessik lauqe htiw meht derewohs dna smra rieht ni pu htob meht depoocs nerdlihc rehto eerht dna ,rehtaf ,rehtom ehT
.don llams a evag dna sevael reh dna
ni dekcilorfnu wodaem on evael ot devloser ehS
nwod kcen reh tneb ehS
.mot elbmuh ,worrom dooG“
!retsum nac uoy liated tsom eht ni em llet nehT“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.erofeb snwot eht raen sdleif eht ni deyalp gnivah ,taehw fo tnecs eht htiw railimaf saw eneleS
egattoc llams a saw ti ot txen dna
,emit eno ta eman rehtona dah I hguoht dna
em otno barg nac yehT
.rednaw ot nevig era ew emit fo ecnatropmi ehT .wohs ot esoprup esohw tirips a saw
.esiw saw eert eht ,ylurT ".yrt
,egdir eht morf dnA
.mrof fo esnes a sa
,hgual a dna krab a htiW
,der dna egnaro thgirb a saw ti semit rehtO
won llet ot retteB