.stneitap llong ni kcitpu elbaton a neeb d’yeht
,evom ot deirt eh nehw ffo deppop romra sih fo stiB
.ksed a dniheb tas ehcatsum etihw debmoc a dna sessalg htiw nam A
,tsaeb suougibma na fo eutats eht ta tfel a gnikat
.edistuo draeh dah ruhtrA eciov eht dias
,aihtnyC dna serutaerc evitcepser eht neewteb gnicnalg thgink eht ,emit trohs a retfA
.serutaef gniyfillong rehto eht htiw gnola
,hE   ?mih tisiv ot sllong ssel tnaw yllaer eh diD
.won rof erutarepmet od ot deen ew kniht t’noD
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
.stnapucco s’moor eht fo
”.ereh ees s'tel ,daerht ffo nettog ev’I ,yawynA“
.wam del-degnaf-wen siht htiw emac taht seiticirtnecce citsiugnil eht ta detartsurf ,demialcxe eh
yletinifeD"  ”.gnorw …s’gniht-muS“  .tluciffid ylbidercni gnivorp saw hteet dna tuons gib siht htiw gnikaeps tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,drawrof denael ruhtrA
,tuons daorb gnol a fo pot no kcalb dna ediw emoceb dah eson siH
”.sevlesmeht fo lluf dna ythgim dna hgih elttil a teg ot dnet nac sthgink fi sa leef I
…saw eh ,eturb a saw eh
.yerfniW .sM siht ,hA“
,pu sbmuht eht htiw gnilims llits llong detciped eht
.ecnatsbus nworb ykrum a htiw top a dellif enihcam egnarts a sa
lanoisacco dna xnijih noitamrofsnart ykriuq otni teg ohw htob
...“ ,gniyas erofeb tnemom a deretsulb eH
.repsihw evitatirohtua na ot eciov sih gnirewol
segap ytiniffAruF evitcepser rieht no dnuof eb nac
.dednetni naht thguoht erom yrtsepat siht gnivig eb thgim eh detcepsus ruhtrA
”!ereh sllewd taht draziw lufrewop eht morf lesnuoc kees I !ruhtrA riS ma I“
.retal emit trohs a yrtsepat eht ot kcab derednaw noitnetta siH
mih edaM .yrtsepat eht fo ebiv eht ekil did eH
.hcuoc dias otno kcab sih otno dna teef sih ffo ruhtrA dekconk neht ,hcuoc yfmoc egral a pu dekcigam draziw ehT
.taht dnim t’nod ,hA“
.sknar s’yerfniW otni thgir uoy htiw gnola ti dnes dna noitadnemmocer fo rettel a etirw ll’I os
,em dna uoy neewteb dna ,enoz eerf tnemgduj a si sihT .did uoy fi melborp oN
noitavresbo ylthgink etuca na neeb dah thguoht d’eh tahw pu gnignirb neve rof ytliug gnileef pleh t’ndluoc ruhtrA dna
.srae dednuor gnilggaw laever ot temleh sih ffo dellup eh
.kcen gnol yrev a fo pot no saw daeh elohw sih dnA
,sraef dna sthguoht s’ruhtrA fo lla hguorht tuc ot demees sdrow ehT
”!esaelp 82 !82“
.oot siht eciton ot demees draziw ehT
gnirebmemer ,gnikniht ,dekrab eh
.tseuq sih no kcab noitnetta sih desucofer eH
.llong a yletulosba saw eh ,tiaw ,on ,oN
.snoitseuq thgir eht ksa dna traeh fo erup eb ot dedeen ylno eno
”.dlrow eht ni ees ot tnaw uoy aneyh eht eB :FLESRUOY LLONG“
,ylisae tuo deppils hcihw
.nalc wen a ni sdneirf wen laitnetop fo stol
,noitcerid lareneg s’ruhtrA ni tuoba dnaw eht delriwt yneeF sA
.srotces cigam krad eht ni yb emoc ot drah era hcihw
,denruter ecived s'aihtnyC fo sdnuos ehT
.boj eht fo esruoc eht gnirud ssorca nur noirrac yna rof sthgir noirrac lluf dnA
”…mrU“  ”?retteb taht sI
,ksed eht ot pu kcab deppils ruhtrA
.rae ytniop rieht fo pit eht no thguac dnik emos fo hsif a htiw fle nA
.gniddib krad reh od ot sllong derih yerfniW lerdnuocs suoirafen eht ,tcaf nI
.rethgit gnitteg romra sih deciton t’ndah ruhtrA
”.dedulcni pukcehc ,nwodnur lluf eht tnaw uoy erus m’I
,flesmih mlac ot detpmetta eH
.tniop taht retfa delddum adnik sdrow ehT
,sllong erom neeb d’ereht ,retsop eht ni stnemtnahcne eht tup d’eh ecniS
!era uoy yppah woh llet nac I“  !lworg deticxE
,ynihs dna dehsilop saw edalb ehT
?tnetni s'yrtsepat eht saw neve tahW
.elbmar ot draziw eht gniwolla ,ecnelis otni dekcohs saw ruhtrA
.nalc sih llacer etiuq t’ndluoc eh fi nevE
?tnetni lanoitavitom fo meti na hcus eriuqer ot hguone yltneuqerf ereh hguorht rednaw sllong diD
!etib dluoc eh syaw eht lla tuoba thguoht eh sa gnihsiws
.part ekil-ebut egnarts a ni thguac saw hcae regnif evitcepser a elihw gniugra sgnilflah owT
”!yneeF em llac nac uoy ,gnikees neeb ev’uoy draziw eht m’I
.modgnik elohw eht ot ronoh gnirb dluow taht edasurc a htiw deksat saw ruhtrA riS
,htuos seugael owt tuoba snoitnetni doog fo htap eht gnikat erofeb
.mih morf ssorca seirtsepat egnarts eht fo eno eciton ot hguone gnol tseuq elbon sih morf derednaw noitnetta siH
!em dednuotsa was I tahw dna yad eno erutuf eht otni dezag I
,ylesolc gniyduts eb ot demees draziw ehT   .ruhtrrU .taht retteb eugnot eht ffo delloR .rruhtrrU
,gnittifer neddus eht morf flesmih gnitcelloc llits ,detrats ruhtrA
.nalc sih ot ronoh gnignirb ta edirp fo hsur A
,ddo sa ruhtrA kcurts noisulcnoc siht tuoba gnihtemoS
.mih ta pu dekool dna ecived reh gnisu desuap tar eht erofeb semit elpitlum taorht sih gniraelc
,sredluohs sih ot pu delevart ecnatsbus lairucrem eht sa eerf deppop tug dna selcsum sih ,mad nori rieht yb kcab dleh regnol oN
daD regdaB yldduC eht
ecived eht otno kcab noitnetta reh desucof tar ehT  ”-I tuB“
draziw evisulcer eht tlusnoc ot evah dluow eh ,taht od ot redro ni tuB
siht fo llems eht ta ecaf sih ffo pmuj ot demees eson s’ruhtrA
.evisnopser ,liaT !peY .yknits
.rehtegot flesmih teg ot dedeen
,sebut leets ynit ylevitarapmoc won eht nepo gnikaerb
.flesmih llonG .peY
,thgisni s’draziw eht niag oT
,kool resolc a noitcelfer sih gnivig
.sbur gnirac ti gnivig
,noitamalcxe eht ot gnimoc erofeb
,kcab demialcxe draziw eht ”!llong taerg a er’uoy ,esnesnoN“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots
,liam s’ruhtrA nwod yaw sti dekans liat yhsurb A
.ksed reh revo gnimool
.skrow gnitirw evitaroballoc
.seiceps evitunimid a hcus rof ,egnartS
?ebyam noisulli nA .laer eb t'ndluoc sihT
,flesmih gnitsujda
.htolcniol elpmis a otni delrufnu seiarb fo riap a ecno saw tahW
.yrtsepat eht ta gnirats deniamer ruhtrA
”!duorp nalc ruoy od ll’uoy
.ti ees dluoc enoyna fi dna ,hsulb dluoc sllong fi derednow ruhtrA
!ereh evirra ot yenruoj ym ni noitalubirt dna lairt decaf dna ecnatsid taerg a emoc ev’I
”!03“   .ffuts otni raet dna etib ot ydaer dna yzzuf dna mraw lla leef
!ruhtrA yas eh t’ndluoc yhw
”.SSENISUB RUOY ETATS“
.noisulcnoc siht morf ssenippah fo zzub a tlef eH
,egde dloc yrev a deniag noisserpxe s’aihtnyC
.ehcadaeh a flesruoy evig lliw ,llong doog ym ,sgniht hcus htiw luferac eb tsuM
,emit tiaw eht tuoba aihtnyC htiw gniugra eugor a eb ot deraeppa tahw tsap gnihsurB  ”!em tahT“
.detaerter dna plug suovren a evag thgink eht litnu ruhtrA no desucof tpek ehs hcihw
.dlot sdnegel eht os rO
,moor a ni gnidnal ylneddus erofeb
.seltrohc gniregnil eht ffo gnittuc
.uoy rof od nac I tahw s’ereH“
?yawyna od gnihtyna tuoba hcum oot gnikniht did doog tahW
?gnorw tnemtnahcne eht derugifnoc d'eh ,spahrep ,eb ti dluoC
.ehcaksut a gnisrun ylgnimees cro nA
,koon emos morf llorcs a tuo gnillup ,dias yneeF
.tnaem taht revetahW
,kool resolc a evig ot llong eht ot revo ,ksed eht dnuora deklaw yneeF
,kcen sih ta dehctarcs eH
.moor eht otni deretlif hgual teiuq A
.flesruoY llonG
,tnemhcrap eht koot ylsuoituac thgink ehT
.tserof eht hguorht yltfiws edor thgink eht sa seert eht hguorht deohce staebfooH
?moor gnitiaw eht ni retsop eht ees uoy t’ndiD“
,ni flesmih dnuof eh noitautis egnarts fo erutan eht etalucitra ot deirt ruhtrA
,tnuoc ot gnitpmetta fi sa wap sih htiw serutseg emos gnikam
?ti saw tahw ,eman sih nevE
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,latrop eht fo tuo gnilbmut emac tiftuo s’feiht gnittif-lli na ni desserd llong rehtona ,emitnaem eht nI
,sriahc drah fo lluf moor egral A
.ylleb yffulf desopxe won s'ruhtrA fo gnivorppa fi sa
.sgel rieht neewteb sliat ,emac yeht ecnehw morf tip eht otni kcab gninnur sllong esoht dnes d’eh ,sthgisni s’draziw eht dessessop ruhtrA ecnO
.dnim sih ni raelc neeb ylsuoiverp dah taht gnihtyreve gnirucsbo eb ot demees ssenllong sih htiw deriap sdrow s’draziw siht tuoba gnihtemoS
”!ni thgir tif ll’uoy erus m’I
.kni ybur thgirb htiw denozalbme
.drows sih fo lemmop eht no swalc sih deppat ruhtrA
,esroh eht morf gnitnuomsiD
,moor eht fo renroc eht morf gnimoc ddo gnihtemos dellems eH
,reweiv eht ta gnikniw dna pu sbmuht a gnivig romra rehtael ni
dna ronoh rof tseuq a
.gnihtemos tuoba drah gnikniht eb ot mees uoY ?ruhtrrU“ .dapeton derujnoc a ni elbbircs lanoisacco eht gnikam
.ris ,doog yreV“   ”.sey...“
,erised I reverehw og nac hguorht emac uoy latrop tahT
.erutnevda wen eht otni latrop eht hguorht depmart thgink llong eht taht htiW
.yawa pils ot nigeb sgniht niatrec tlef eH
,thgink llong a sediseb eb ot desoppus saw eh tahw no walc a tup etiuq t’ndluoc eh hguoht dnA
”!tsewq dah I !tsewQ“   ”?htiw tsissa nac I esle gnihtynA
.ni flesmih dnuof eh ydob wen eht gnithgilhgih lla ti
,esoprup tsafdaets nwo reh htiw ,deksa aihtnyC
.semit ta segde eht dnuora ylddif tib a eb ot demees stluser cigam lanoitavitoM
.ti nopu detnirp 03 rebmun eht gnilaever
.dekrep srae s’rruhtrrU  ”!uoy ekil sllong gnuoy gnipparts gnirih elpoep ynam era ereht taht wonk I lleW“
.kcen sih ssorca daerps taht tlep ruf eht otni peed swalc wen siH
”…rM uoy pleh I nac woH
.rebmun eht gnikees neht
,thgink tnailav a sa flesmih fo thguoht syawla dah eH
.kcab detcelfer ecaf sih was eh ,latem eht otni dekool ruhtrA nehw taht os
.ruhtrA xaler did llong gnilims eht fo egami detniap ehT
.noitom regnif gnihsuhs a mih evig dna pu kool ot aihtnyC gnisuac yliraropmet
,rovaf s'gnik eht mih nrae dluow os gnioD
,noe na ekil tlef tahw rof rehte eht hguorht delbmut eH
.ybraen elpoep fo puorg a fo rethgual eht draeh eh raews dluoc ruhtrA ,siht dias eh retfA
,erutaerc laitnedor a tas ksed a ta moor eht fo renroc eht nI
”?TNEMTNIOPPA NA EVAH UOY DID“
.detniap saw siht nehw gniod erew yeht revetahw ta desuma yrev ylraelc
.llew meht staert dna sllong ot gnikil a saH .seY“   .lworg gniriuqnI
.tsac cigam eht fo sretemarap eht tif ”xif“ ot deirt ti esoht ekam ot detavitom ,llew ,eb ot dednet noitavitom lacigaM
.mih ot gnimoc s’tahw teg ot gniog saw gnik einaem taht ,sulP
.netsil dna taes a ekat esaelp lliw uoy fi ,woN
tnemecnuonna eht yb stcilfnoc lanretni sih morf detcartsiD
”tseuQ elbllonG A“   yojne esaelP
htaerb peed a koot thgink ehT
”.uoy no sucof nac ew os yliraropmet ffo taht nrut dna daeha og nac I
.gniknalc romra sih
,yrtsepat ddo eht ta kcab kool ot denrut eh nehw gnalc a htiw dednal etalptsaerb sih dna
”.latrop eht ot deecorp esaelp 92 !92“  -uh a ,a-ng-ng a saw ,tnemtnahcne siht tsap teg ot dedeen eh ,no emoC
tuoba gnihtemos gniyas pac ynihs a htiw namuh naem a tuoba gnihtemos
pu gnittup ecnis revE .hguoht mih elzzup did gnihtemoS .riahc ksed sih ta kcab gnittis ,thguoht draziw eht ”,dik doog a tahW“
.rruhtrrU ,og ew erehT“
,ti fo tuo gnikcits tnemhcrap fo pils a
,elcsum htiw dellews dna tuo deffup smra sih
”?ris ,rebmun a evah uoy oD“
:daer erutaerc eht woleb noitpac ehT
.gnidnats wohemos
,ruhtrA ,ti gnaD  ”!rruhtrrU !rruhtrrU ?rruht…rU“
,weiv fo tniop sih morF
,daor gnidniw dna gnol eht fo dne eht gnihcaer nopU
.dnaw a tuo koot draziw ehT
.elgna s’drows eht gnitsujda
”.lliw uoy fi ,retsop lanoitavillong ehT
,roloc rehco na ot gnitfihs seye ees ot emit nI
!mrof wen egnarts a otni desruC
,retsop lanoitavitom taht
.mih gnipacse sralucitrap eht tub ,gnik
,nees reve d’eh seirtsepat tsegnarts eht htiw detaroced sllaw egieb eht dna
.lworg detseretnI
.rebmemer ot redrah neve saw egaugnaL
erom dnif nac uoY ..daD regdaB yldduC eht ,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,smloH oeG dna xoF .T ippaL yb
.maerd tnatsid a ekil leef ot nageb eriuqs a sa gniniart siH
rewop reh deifidilos dah ehs ,kool taht ylerem morF
.noissim sih no sucofer ot dedeen eH  ”!72“   .latrop eht tsap tog eh ecno ecin llems thgim sgniht rehto tahw tuoba thguoht eh ,elims yhtoot ediw a htiw dnA ”.flac-eed“
.erofeb naht desufnoc dna sseltsil erom spahrep
!romra tahT .ereh gnorw gnihtemos
.gnittifer romra rof ylerem ereh emoc t’ndid uoy erus m’I“
,nogard a gnitciped eutats nedlog llams a gnidloh dlobok A
,wed gninrom s’tnim a elpmas ,lidoffad tsethgirb eht otni repsihw
,tuoba decnuob draziw eht
,relevart wollef ruoy
.dnal eht tuohguorht morf htap eht dewollof ohw sgnieb rehto eht fo emos deciton ruhtrA ,taes a gnikaT
,yzzuf worg ot ytilaer dna nwod dna pu fo noitpecrep rof hguone gnol
”.tros doog a eb ot demeeS
,ybraen gnidnats noitpartnoc gnimussanu llams a deciton eH
,eert eht dehcaorppa ylsuoituac thgink eht
.evloser sih deretnecer dah latrop eht hguorht pirt ehT
”.42“ rebmun eht saw
.esoprup htiw ksed eht ot revo deppets eH
.mih pleh ot elba eb dna gnorw saw gnihtemos wonk dluow draziw siht wenk eh
,ytilaer siht ni snoinim sa snoitisop rieht ot eud tsoob ecnedifnoc a deen ot demees saneyh gnitisiv eht llA
.niamod siht ni ytirohtua fo rettam emos gnissessop sa thgink eht kcurts erutaerc eht tuoba gnihtemoS
”.YLTROHS UOY HTIW EB LLIW EVITATNESERPER A DNA REBMUN A EKAT“
?sllong dnuora deretnec yrtsepat a evah dluow draziw gnitcepser-fles tahW .delbmurg ruhtrA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.draug ffo thgink eht thguac hcihw ,noitaralced detpmetta s’thgink eht yb devomnu
,gniraelc llams a nihtiw deltseN
.kcen dna smra sih morf yawa stcejbo ytniop yna peek ot sdraug gnimrof
!rruhtrrU emac ereh ,dlrow tuo kooL
?swalc dna swaj ekil ffuts dah eh nehw drows a deen eh did yhW ?drowS
.drawrof denael eH
.nac eht denethgit dna pu dekcip yneeF
.lleps a gnitsac naht rehtar ffuts tuo gnikcehc fi sa ,ruhtrA fo strap gnippat ,tuoba dnaw sih gnivom
”-htiw ecneidua evah ot eeht hceeseb tsum I
.nosrep ynniW eht…etib…ot yaw tseb eht
…rruhtrU …rruhtrA …ruhtrA
,dias eh ”?yd-ruhT“
.kool suoiruc a ti gnivig
,flesmih koohs ruhtrA
.smloHoeG dna xoFippaL ta
.edalg detnahcne eht nihtiw peed devil ohw
?llong bmud a eb sediseb gnihtyna od llong a diD
.erofeb ti ekil gnihton nees dah ruhtrA
,flesmih fo noinipo sih gnitfihs tpek tI
.ti fo niatrec saw eH
.aedi taerg a ekil dednuos ,haey kceH
.srettam lla ni modsiw s’draziw eht fo llet draeh d’eH
?yawyna ,naem neve ”flesruoy llong“ did tahW  .mih gnikcom ylgnimees saw elims yepod s’llong eht
.thgink eht ffo sucof dloc reh denrut dah ehs gnilangis
.rehtie stneitap llong erom gnivah dednim ohw draziw a t’nsaw yneeF
.yrassecen sa no yrotirret kram ro no etib ro no walc neht
tuoba draziw eht ksa ot gnioG .esruoc fO !seY
,nwod kcab tas eh sa dehgis thgink ehT
.yhw erugif etiuq t’ndluoc eh ,revewoh
.eert eht otni ecnartne neddih otrehtih a gnilaever ,gnidaf erofeb
,dnik emos fo skoob niht ,egnarts htiw derevoc elddim eht ni elbat a htiw
.swap tnaig rieht ta yldesufnoc gnikool
,erofeb ytud fo esnes a tlef dah eH
”2 LATROP HGUORHT DEECORP ESAELP 52 REBMUN LLIW“ .ti otni ekops dna ebut latem ynihs emos detfil erutaerc tar ehT
,rebmun eht gnikat nopU
,retsnom a saw eH
,htlaeh fo llib naelc a ,boj wen a ,saw siht yad doog a tahW
.yarra nottub egnarts sti ta yawa gnikcilc detrats dna
.tniop emos ta yranidro eht fo tuo gnihtyna was ehs fi aihtnyC ksa ot evah d’eh
!walc dna etiB  …tiaW
.yfiuqil ot demees romra gniniamer s’thgink llong eht pu edam taht latem eht
!ruhtrA riS“   ”-ris ,olleH“
,kao tsedlo eht fo knurt eht elffurcs
"?thgir ,retteb krow thgim tnemegnarra htolcniol a kniht dna ytilibom reporp rof resool tib a ti ekam ll'ew gniknihT
,etagitsevni ot ffuts ta ffins tsuj ot retteb hcuM
?nalc a tuohtiw eb llong a dluow tahW ?thgiR .nalc a evah t’ndid eh ,tiaw ,oN
!gnikaeps llongoitavitom rof yad ysub a eb ot gniog s’ti ekil smeeS
.gnihtemos gnihtemoS
eh…dna gnorts dna yffurcs dna gnitadimitni ylreporP
,noziroh gniremmilg sti hguorht deraeppasid dna latrop a ot revo derednaw cro eht sA  ”!62 REBMUN“
.retteb dna retteb gnidnuos tpek tsuJ   ”.boj
.nosrep ynniW taht tuobA
ruhtrA ta pu dekool ehs ,tnemecnuonna eht gnitelpmoc retfA
.ecitsuj ot reh gnirb ot boj s’thgink eht saw ti os
.llong a eb ot dedeen tsuj eH
?gnorw tnemtnahcne eht teg eh diD
era ohw ,smloH oeG dna  xoF .T ippaL yb ”tseuQ elbllonG A“
.aihtnyC eman eht saw trihs reh no denozalbmE
,drabbacs sti morf tuo drows eht dellup eH
,esiwrehto dna evitaroballoc ,seirots riehT
”.latrop detats eht ot deecorp lliw uoy ,dellac si rebmun ruoy nehW
.yawa detaolf tuons a htiw ecnuonorp ot drah oot sthguoht dna sdroW
”!ega ruoy llong a rof htlaeh tcefrep ni er’uoy smeeS
.thguoht eht ta delkcuhc ruhtrA
.tsaeb suortsnom a saw eh tpecca ot dnim sih teg ot delggurts ruhtrA  ?emosdnah
.ecived eht morf dednuos gnid thgils a ,eriuqni dluoc eh erofeB
,soahc otni gnillaf morf mlaer eht dnuob taht swal fo sllorcs dercas eht fo emos nelots dah yerfniW lerdnuocs suoirafen ehT
.htron eht fo stnaig tseggib eht naht rellat dna terrut eltsac a sa ediw sa knurt a dah eert eht
,em teem ot desaelp yllaer er’uoy llet nac I
”tseuQ elbllonG A“ saw sihT
:htrof emac eciov gnimoob a nehw
smloH oeG dna xoF .T ippaL yb
?llong a ot ytud saw esu tahw tub
,modsiw fo sesarhp lareneg ro ,selddir ,slleps erew sdrow eht rehtehW
:rettel eht ot llorcs dedaf eht fo snoitcurtsni eht dewollof eH
.tnemom eht ni hguone hgih llor ton did noitpecrep s’ruhtrA
erutaerc aneyh gnilims a fo erutcip a fo detsisnoc tI
.sdrow htiw deriap seiceps fo segami detniap
?thgink emoselbuort a ffo taht egnevacS .tif elbirreT
,liat ruoy fo gaw eht morf ,rruhtrrU ,woW“
.dehgis eciov ehT  ”?on…“
”!od ot gnihtemos deen uoy ,hO“
.netfo daert t’ndid eh dnim sih fo trap a ot nwod
,depley/lworg/tuohs eH ”!haG“
?seiceps evitcepser rieht rettam on ,sllong retteb sa sevlesmeht fo kniht retsop eht ta dezag ohw enoyreve ekam ti diD
"?tsdim ruoy ni serutaerc lufraef era ereht taht
.egap a no txet otni sesserp nottub detalsnart taht ecived lacinahcem fo dnik emos no gnikrow
.edam dah draziw siht senihcam luficnaf tahW
.meht fo tol eht ,seturb bmud nettib-aelF
.sevlesmeht fo retteb kniht ot emac ohw sllong teg ot aedi doog a saw ti thguoht eh os
?noonretfa na yawa gniffaf ekil erom yllautca saw tuo denrut taht tseuq cipe sih no gnikees neeb d’eh draziw eht siht saW
.tuoba dekool dna deknilb ruhtrA riS
.llong gnikool enif a saw eh gnitsisni
,kcen sih nwod dna daeh sih fo kcab eht tuo gnifoolf ruf yffurcs fo enam a
,ot desu saw eh naht rekciht raf sgel sih htiw dna ,ffo gnillaf nageb seceip romra rehtruF
.daeh sih no yldriew tif ot temleh sih gnisuac
.tneitap egareva eht naht retuc ,noitpo demeetse s’draziw eht ni tsael ta ,dna ,evitaicerppa erom ,esongaid ot reisae erew yehT
,mrof llong suortsnom won sih ot noitcaer tnalahcnon s'draziw eht ta ffo nworhT
,ksed sih no nac nepo na desolc dna pu dekcip yneeF
.mlaer egnarts siht ni egatnavda s’tar eht detamitserednu dah eh ,ylsuoivbO
level eye evoba tsuj  krab eht otni dehctE
.latrop eht hguorht tsrif daeh gnillaf ,deppirt ruhtrA
,ylthgirb wolg ot nageb krab eht fo noitces a
”!7991 fo raey ffo raf eht ni sgniht od ot woh wonk yllaer yeht ,seY
.eert eht deretne dna
.resool dna resool gnimoceb ,oot tfihs ot demees stnemragrednu siH
.nees reve d’eh eert tsegral eht eb ot deraeppa tahw nopu emac thgink eht
.noisacco siht rof tsuj lleps krowlatem gniroliat a htiw ereh pu dexif romra taht teg nac eW“
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.yrtsepat eht nopu kcab llef noitnetta sih
.noissim a htiw gnihtemoS .haeY .noissim ehT .noissim ehT
.ytilbissop siht gniredisnoc ,thguoht ni ehcatsum sih debbur eH
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,snoitcerruser citnamorcen-non sulP .htlaeH .latneD .stifeneb lluF
,elihw a ni denimaxe ev'I sllong tseb eht fo eno er’uoy ,yltsenoH“
!llong a eb ot desoppus t’nsaw eh ,won llong a saw eh hguoht dnA !thgink a saw eH
.llong a ton ,llong a saw eH
!yadot eciffo ym ni llong gnuoy emosdnah a tahw ,yM“
.liat sih ot gaw a thguorb sdrow s’draziw doog eht tuoba gnihtemos tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
…htaerB .pey ,yrruF .kcehc ,giB …ereh ees s’teL“
?esarhp taht morf teg neve llong a dluow tahW
,ssim ,erawa uoy erA"
?ereh dnuora peek I secived lacismihw eht yb dezama uoy erA“
.ssenhgih layor sih fo ecivres ni seitud erom no ekat ot mih wolla dluow dna
.latrop eht sdrawot delbmuts ruhtrA
,ylevitcepser ,nooccar suoveihcsim dna xof cidrab a
”!dug ton ,llonG ma …I“
.pu derujnoc d’eh hcihw bmoc dehtoot-enif a htiw ruf s’ruhtrA revo gniog yllaretil
.gniyfsitas erom eht lla noitca siht gnikam swalc ot detfihs gnivah slianregnif sih