,dap gnitaeh a htiw emit ytilauq emos deen ot gniog si kcab yM
.llup ot ssenrah sih barg neht dna
.sdem gninrom sih dah s’eh erofeb yllaicepse
”.ffuts hguor eht gniod t’nerew ew thguoht I“
.rae ot rae morf gninnirg ,syas eh
ediw seog elttob ehT ”!hctaC“
,smuc eh sa gnirepmihw dna gniredduhs s’eh ,sdnoces wef a ylno nI
,htaehs ym kcab llup ot wap a sesu eH ”.krow ot teG“
.teef ym ot em steg pley a nehT
,mih rof laiceps eb ot gniog si keew siht fi tub
.yppup a ekil liat sih gaw dna elims mih gnihctaw—
”.etunim a em eviG .eniF“
evitisnes tsom m’I secalp eht fo lla swonk eH
.gnikrow s’ti ,emit sihT
.uoy llik ll’I dna taht oD“
.sih ot eson ym hcuot ot revo nael I
.delzzarf erom steg liat sih tub
.noitisop gnileenk a otni pu flesym hsup I os
”,pup yssas eno er’uoY“
,.m.p 4 tuoba s’tI
tekcop sih ni enohp sih stup eH ”.yllaniF“
.taht htiw pleh dluow evitca mih gnipeeK
”.desaet gnieb ekil uoy ,sediseb dnA .struh kcab yM“
,tsurht rehtona retfA
.ylhsipeehs seilper eh ”,haeY“ ”?yako uoY“
.kcab dlof srae siH
,gnol a otni mih llup dna
”!krow rof etal eb annog er’uoY
.kcab dedlof srae sih htiw gab eht ta skool eH
.mih evig nac I naht ti fo erom—
.kcen sih hctarcs dna ronoC ot txen nwod tis I
retsaf dna ,thgiew ym flah ,regnuoy si ronoC
,noacyL edoyaK yb ”yadnoM yzaL A“
.srepmihw dna senihw ronoC
.deb ot og ew erofeb tsuj ffo dewap gnieb rof selttes eh sthgin ynam oS
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”?uoy elzzum ot deen I oD“
.rae sih ni repsihw I ”,uoy evol I“
eeffoc gniknird m’I
.thgin tsal denoisivne dah I gnildduc citnamor eht ot pu gnikaw rof hcum oS
.senihw eh ”,no emoC“
.neercs eht ta gnippat sekaf dna enohp sih tuo steg eH .psag I
.kraP ediskcoR ot elim txen eht evivrus I ,wohemoS
,hcterts dna pu tis I
?em esirprus uoy t’ndluoC“
,wols shtaerb siH
”.em ot ti revo ti ssap tsuj ,emit txeN“
,ni gnidils ylwols erofeb pu su fo htob
.elzzum gnol sih otni htgnel eritne ym sekat ylisae eH
.noitacidem sih etipsed elbatsnu emoceb ylkciuq dluoc eh
.yllufepoh sksa eh ”?dluow uoY“
nehctik eht ni gnidnats ronoC dnif dna moordeb eht fo tuo hsur I
ebircsed lehcaR gnirebmemer ,elims I
,redluohs sih revo kcab skool eH
# # # ”.em htiw er’uoy fi ylnO“ .elims a htiw
,erofeb did eh sa ylgnorts sa kcab gnihsup t’nsi eH
.daeh sih fo pot eht ssik ot nwod dneb dna
ffo erusserp eht sekat gnivoM
.si siht emosewa woh tegrof syawla I yhw rednow I dna
edis ym tsniaga snael ronoC
”ekaL nedraG kraD“ yrots siH
.deb eht fo edis etisoppo eht no reward dnatsthgin eht otni sehcaer ronoC
.sredluohs eht neewteb ylerauqs em stih wollip emas eht sa tnurg I ”,kcuF“
.kcoc ym no sbrab eht ssorca sehsurb eugnot sih neht
sredduhs liat yM
”…sleef eh woh em llet dluow flow eht fI“
”!setunim net ni si niart txen ehT“
.regnif a htiw eson sih ekop I
.reerac gnitirw sih tuo gnitrats tsuj si ohw
.muc ot gnikorts hcum deen t’now eh
.yab eht gnikoolrevo knab etercnoc eht no hcneb a ot tuo klaw ew ,elihw a retfA
,flesym pots nac I erofeB
.sruof lla otno sllor dna em rednu morf tuo selggiw eh nehT
.redduhs a htiw em otni kcab sehsup eh nehT
t’nia sihT“ .flesmih ti od ot gnivah ekil t’nseod yllaer eh dna
,gnillaf llits era seirrulf wons thgiL
.tuop kcom a ni smialcxe eh ”!ti gnaD“
.sih otni htaehs ym dnirg dna
.nwod wols I sa em rednu stfihs ronoC .gnol ooT
”.ereht tsomla saw I“
nissassa tnatculer a tuoba
,ekatsim a si ronoC gnisirprus semitemoS
flow detniap suoiragerg a
,retnuoc eht no si sserp hcnerF ehT .esruoc fo ,dekan—
”?nehw siht em llet ot gniog erew uoy dnA“
.tseb sdnatsrednu eh yaw eht ni mih evol I wohs ot ygrene eht dnif ot deen I
,ecrof eht fo tnurb eht ekat meht gnittel ,seot sih no ylkciuq gniklaw s’eH
”.htuom ruoy ni kcoc ym htiw klat uoy llew woh ees s’teL“
edis eht ni em swoble yllufyalp ronoC
”?erom elttil a pu tfil uoy naC
# # DNE # # .ot gniog ton m’I tub
.detnioppasid s’eh nehw od syawla yeht yaw emas eht gas srae sih dna em ta kool ot snrut eH
”.ffo keew eht koot I“
.niaga tuo llup I dna pu dloh ot gniog t’nsi kcab ym ,yletanutrofnU
.sih htiw elzzum ym sbarg yllufyalp eH
”.wollip taht tae ot gniksa er’uoY“
.kcab ym gnibbur ,eil I ”,enif m’I ,haeY“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,yltnetni em ta gnirats ,pu krep srae siH
.yalp meht sehctaw eh sa sgaw liat sih tub sbuc fo tnarelot eb ot ronoC deredisnoc reven d’I
”—ot ecnahc eht dah aY“  .lworg I
”.troffe eht lla hguorht enog gnivah retfa detnioppasid ythgim eb d’I dna gnihtaerb tsuj tuo nrow lla eb d’uoy ,t’nod I fI“
,tsehc ym tsniaga stser ronoC
.tuo eugnot sih skcits eH
.rae sih ni repsihw I ”…erucesni ,pu dekcuF“ ”.sseug I ,eniF“
,dennalp gnihtyna evah t’nod ew tub raf elttil a s’ti ,selim eerht tA
”.detnaw I naht retal kcab tog I dna hguoht gnol oot em kooT“
.deen I lla si lworg lufyalp siH
.yllacitamard slialf eH
,ni kcab flesym edils I sA
.redaer koob sih morf pu skool eH  .rrup I
”.ixat eerf a gnitnaw elpoep morf erew sllac gnikcuf ym fo flaH
?gnippohs yrecorg tnew uoY“
.waj sih nepo ot rehto eht esu dna wap eno ni noitcere ym barg I
.ni ylluf flesym hsup I ,delttes s’eh nehW
,rehto hcae ot txen deb eht no polf eW
”.ssaM retsaE rof eceeR dna enuJ nioj dna siweL ot pu daeh ot ekil d’I ,dnim t’nod uoy fi dnA“
traeh yb eludehcs niart eht swonk eh tub era stset sih nehw rebmemer t’nac flow roop yM .hgual I
.tuo dna ni swalc ym gnikrow
.tuoba desaet eb ot sekil eh gnihtemos ton—
,delttes sah tsafkaerb ruo nehW
.gnitnap era su fo htob ,gnol erofeB
eeffoc ym fo pis a ekat I
.pu krep srae siH
”.krap eht ot edir a ekil dluow dna derit si dneirf yM
”?snalp yna evah uoy diD“
.pu kcab dliub ot emit gnol a em sekat ti ,ma I sa regae dna drah sA
”.yllacirohpateM“
.stnurg eh dna sih otni mals spih yM
.stsirw sih tuo sdloh dna
”,tnemom a rof pots ew naC“
.tnemom eht rof sesae
.yllacitamard shgis eH
.mynorca eht gnihsinif ,snaorg eh
.ffur kcen sih hguorht swap ym gninnur ,ksa I
”.enif s’taht ,hcuoc eht no peels ot tnaw uoy fI“
.dnuorgyalp eht fo elddim eht ni eltsac nedoow gnilwarps eht no dnuora nur
.niaga ydaer m’I erofeb elihw a em ekat dluow ti
.seenk sih stsujda eh sa tib a stnap ronoC .yawflah gnisuap
erom fo yaw eht ni teg ot ylekil tsael si noitacidem sih nehw emit eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
ihsus fo hcnul etal a retfa emoh teg eW
”.ysae siht gnikam er’uoY“
”!deb eht no teG .neht ,yakO“
.mih sdrawot edis ym otno llor I ,esle gnihtemos worht nac ronoC erofeB
.eugnot sih tuo kcits ot em gnikcil spots eH ”.hsuH“
.deb eht fo daeh eht ta skool eH ”.t’nac I“
”—ti hctac tsuj d’uoy fI“
.gniksa tuohtiw wonk ot em rof llew oot ti sedih eH .ksa I ”?yteixna ruoy s’woH“
.gel sih dnuora liat yffulf
.deb eht otno smaerts etihw kciht gnitrups
.retteb sleef kcab ym dna
.nrecnoc htiw kcab srae sih ,sksa eh ”?yako uoY“
!deb atuo liat gnikcuf ruoy teg
# # # .seerga eh ”,thgirlA“
.xaler srae sih dna ,esolc seye sih
.em sdrawot mih llup dna ssenrah s’ronoC barg I nehT
”,yadot daeha raf taht nalp t’ndid I .paC ,yrroS“
,gnol ym parw I
”.evaheb ll’I“ .og em stel eh nehT
.sgge fo tuo erew ew
.ylteiuq syas ronoC
.liat sih fo gniggaw eht htiw sekahs deb ehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.uoy htiw pu og ll’I dna nehw wonk em teL“
ebul I ”.ti gnihctac eb ot gniog er’uoY“
,od I fi esuaceb htuom sih ni muc t’nod I os kcab mih hsup ot evah I .gnipsag m’I litnu gniog speek ronoC
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.flesym leets I dna
.ylippah shgis eh elihw esolc mih dloh em gnittel
.klaw a rof tuo og ew
”?noitacidem yteixna ruoy ekat uoy diD
”?em gnillet tuohtiw ffo keew eht ekat dna og uoy did yhw oS“
,thgir ti od I fI
”.won morf sruoh owt tuobA“
.gel ym tsniaga sbur htaehs siH
,dloc eht tsniaga pu deldnub ,sbuc gnimaercS
?tsaot gnirettub naht
,spmuj flah ronoC
.kcab dlof srae siH
,msaisuhtne sih etipseD
mih fo trap a syawla s’taht noisnet ehT
”.taht ot eerga nac I esoppus I“
sparts redluohs sih barg I sa sgaw liat siH
.hgual a pots t’nac I ,suoires enot ym peek ot tpmetta ym etipseD ”.do‘
”.worromot uoy ot pu ti ekam ll’I“
.ti hctac ot tpmetta neve t’nod I dna
kcab edils ylwols I
,ni selim owt tuobA
.lla ta enon ,semitemoS
.spsag eh ”,gnikrow
”.wollip denmad-dog a em barG“
?nuf rof snohtaram-flah snur dnabsuh ym tegrof I did woh ,tsirhC
,em tsniaga kcab gnihsup strats eh
”yadnoM yzaL A“ saw sihT
”,meht fo htob deen ll’uoy ,owt ekaT“
.daeh s’ronoC gnibbur ,yas I
.thgil eht tsniaga knilb I
.niaga trats dna sevlesruo egnarraer eW
”,’ninrom eht ni ylrae siht ysub oot t’niA .oN“
.em rof raf oot si kraP ediskcoR fi sksa ronoC
”?tsrif ffo uoy teg I fi tahW“
.tiaw nac pu gninaelc
”.eeffoc ruoy teg I elihw desserd teg ot setunim eerht tog uoY“
.hcaer nac I tub ,struh tI
.tnemom a rof sleeh ym no tser I ”!no emoC“
em ta pu skool eh nehT
.kcoldaeh a otni mih tup I dna
.niaga ssenrah sih gnibbarg erofeb
mih llet t’nod I tahW
”.hcuoc eht no gnipeels gnieb erehwemos tahT“
.mih ta nwod elims dna
.devlovni oot t’nsi ti sa gnol sA“
.wonk ot deen I gnihtyreve em llet srae denettalf siH
.deb eht ot mih gard dna sparts edis sih fo eno barg ot swap ym fo eno tfihs I
.ti eveirter ot deb eht ffo teg ot evah I
.redduhs em ekam skcus dna skcil eltneg siH
.detartsurf gnitteg s’eh llet nac I ,gnol erofeB
guh a otni mih llup I
.srae eht neewteb mih ssik I dna
.em ot ylppa t’nseod
.ruf revlis dna kcalb fo rulb a ni moor eht fo tuo sehsur neht ,senihw ronoC
.si eh sa ylivaeh sa tsuj gnitnap m’I nehT
,em ecaf ot snrut eH
.elims llams a em sevig eh
.ffo mih teg ot hguone drah tsurht t’nac I tub esolc s’eH
.elgna doog a teg t’nac ew dna
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.keehc sih no ssik mih evig I ”.esruoc fO“
”.doog ti ekam uoy fI“
.tsaf dna drah stsurht eh dna
.ssenrah nolyn der sih otni flesmih depparts s’eh ecno sehsinav tnemtnioppasid s’ronoC
,noacyL edoyaK yb
”,tuo dnif dluow lehcaR“
nirg a htiw seilper eh ”,wonk I“
.ti ekat t’nac kcab yM“
.ti ot eerga I os
”.taht tbuod I ,wohemoS“
sevresed dna—stnaw ronoC esuaceb ekatsim a saw taht dna xes saw tuoba gnikniht saw I gniht tsal eht ,ffo keew eht koot I nehW
.ksirb si erutarepmet eht dna
.eltsac emas eht gnimrots devlovni taht emag PRAL thgin etal a
”!erehT“ .snaom eh dna
.erehwyreve dehsalps si retaw dna
.stsurht kciuq ,trohs htiw mih remmah I sa em tsniaga mih llup dna lworg I
.ylsselhtaerb ksa I
”,ebul eht em hctef dna flow doog a eb ,yakO“
.nocab dna ,otamot ,sgge hcum oot raf htiw deffuts era su fo htoB
,elttek cirtcele eht gnidloh si rekaertS niatpaC
”.srepap fo elpuoc a toG“
,drapoel wons yzal ay ,navonoD“
.gnileef m’I gnitloj lufniap eht morf kcab sih gnivas
.kcab sih otno spolf flah
.gniog teg ew tuoba woH“
.cidemarap a sa reerac ym dedne taht tnedicca eht erofeb
.wap ym ni daeh ym dloh I
”.nikpmup a otni nrut edir ym evah dna dnuora llor .m.p 8 ees ot etaH
tuo gniog keew a dneps ot naht erom tnaw I gnihton s’erehT
enO raeY - tcejorP noitamalceR ehT ni sraeppa
.kcab sih gnihcra
,esirprus ym ot nehT
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
;tsaot ro laemtao gnieb ylbaborp tsafkaerB
”.etunim a em eviG“
”.sessalc yna evah t’nod dna kaerb gnirps no ffo er’uoY“ .sksa ronoC
,sregnif ym gnilruc
.ekatsim a edam ev’I ezilaer I
.liat gniggaw sih barg I
”.detnioppasid yleros eb ot gniog er’uoy ,bojwolb a uoy yub annog si ihsus fo srallod ytnewt kniht ay fI“ .delruf sworb
.ylsselhtur egdelwonk taht sesu dna
,esimorp dna yltneg mih guh I
,ffo mih wap ot nwod hcaer d’I ,gnimaercs t’nerew kcab ym fI
spih ym gnirewol yrt I
.em ta skool eh nehw kcab srae sih sdlof dna eciuj sih spis eH
”?dnim ni evah ahctahW“
”,ot deen t’noD“ ”.em ekaM“
.tsafkaerb ekam ot emit fo ytnelp s’ereht woN“
,esle gnihtyna yas nac eh erofeB ”oN“
.dniw eht ni gnilriws sekalfwons llams hctaw dna
.emoh ta yats ot denilcni oot yleritne era ew ,enola era su fo rehtie nehw ,sediseB
twan“ ,selbmum eh nehT
.redaer koob sih htiw hcuoc eht no pu slruc ronoC elihw tnemtrapa eht gninaelc dna yrdnual gnidlof no krow I
# # # ”.dnekeew siht gnikrow m’I stnerap ym dlot I“
”.tsafkaerb uoy ekam d’I thguohT“
”.erehwemos gnitteg era ew won ,dooG“
,hgih desiar liat
.keehc eht no mih ssik I ”.ekil
.tsehc ym ot mih gnidloh ,ksa I ”?ydaer uoY“
skeew ni emit tsrif eht rof ni gnipeels m’I
”.rehtegot emit emos dneps dluoc ew derugiF“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
devlovni erom gnihtyna gniod erofeb strohs emos no tup tsael ta ot mih deksa I evah semit ynam woH
.nirg a em steg tahT
.sredluohs sih no stser mra ym elihw
,ylwols tuo sehtaerb eH
”.em esirprus uoy nehw ekil I
etisbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,tenalPruF yb
”,lanoitome dna citorueN“
uoy revetahW“
,epahs a fo doog taht ni saw I ecnis emit gnol a neeb s’tI
.hsipeehs kool ot nrut ym s’tI
.mih fo pot no pu bmilc I sa yas I
.redluohs sih revo ti sworht neht dna ebul eht steg eH
.sekil eh eciuj yrrebnarc ytsan taht fo gum a sah ronoC dna
.tniartser htiw syas eh
.niaga gnuoy leef em sekam mih dnuora gnieb tsuJ
# # # ”?gnippot rof pu eb kcab ruoy dluoW“
,kcart no eludehcs peels sih peek ot sessalc tuohtiW
.oot muc ot em rof gnol ekat t’nseod ti tub
kcoc sih dnuora sparw wap yM
.ti htrow lla ti sekam smra ym ni flow gnilims ym gnidloh tub
.retrohs toof a gnieb etipsed
,elahw detaolb a ekil gnileef pots I ecnO
.daeh ym rednu morf tuo deknay si wollip eht dna no deppilf era sthgil nehw
”.edir siht rof diap ev’I ,yggod pu yddiG“ .ttub sih pals I
.snoitacifiton radnelac dna senohptrams rof doG knahT
.flesym gnikcik yllatnem elihw ezigolopa I
dlrow eht ni esle enoyna naht erom mih evol I swonk eH
.roolf eht otno sllaf dna resserd eht tsniaga spmuht tI
.swap ym fo htob htiw ssenrah sih dloh ot og tel I sa ylivaeh stnap eH
?elbaliava ecnalubma na tog lla’y ,ereht iH“
.ecniw dna kcab ym bur I
,taht od t’nac I tub
”,moordeb eht ni gnihtemos od ot ekil uoy dluoW“
.drawnwod stsurht ym elgna I
”?ecnalubma na llac ot em deeN“
.seitivitca suoroma
”.ylrae os pu eb ot uoy tcepxe t’ndid I“
.keehc ym no ruf eht selffur eson sih morf htaerb toH .ssik tuo-nward
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.mih gnikcams morf peek ot seot ym hcnelc ot evah I dna ,lufniap tsomla si noitasnes ehT
rood ynoclab eht ot revo klaw ew ,tsafkaerb retfA
.tuo eugnot sih skcits eH ”.deyonnA“
;edam ew ssem eht tuoba gnirac ton
rewols gnitsurht m’I
”.od ew tahw ’nidiced syawla m’I ,no emoC“ ”.devlovni
:yojne esaelP  .oc.edoyak
.senituor sih pu gnissem kaerb eht tuoba deirrow m’I si
,deb eht no kcab m’I ecnO
deb ni stac tuoba yas elpoep gnihtyrevE
.aet enimsaj hcum oot yleritne dna
”.tsrif strohs emos no tup tsuJ
.elbat eht no gab yrecorg eht eciton I nehT
”.flow tneconni roop a no gnikcip potS“
noacyL edoyaK yb ”yadnoM yzaL A“
.spih sih sekahs dna
,ffo keew eritne eht gnikat em terger ot gniog si ydob yM
mih elddarts I sa selggig eH
,kcab ym ni thgit gnitteg elcsum a leef I
.revo nael dna flesym ecarb ot htaerb a ekat I
rethgiarts kcab ym dloh ot seenk ym tfihs I .selbmurg ronoC
.euqinhcet sih yvne I
.nwod elttek eht stes eh retfa yas I ”,xaler nac uoY“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
”.desaet eb annaw I semit esoht fo eno t’nia sihT“