fo esnepxe nepo eht deyevrus eH
.esruoc fo ,oot rehtom ruo dna
.erutats sih rof yllufecarg rehtar ti dedne eh dna
.evom retfa evom evisolpxe
sgel dna tsehc sih ssorca selcsuM
gnignoleb fo esnes eht tlef eh sa enips sih hguorht llihc a tlef tuaseL
detelpmoc eh sa neve gnirit reven
.ytic taht tuoba srehto morf draeh eh tahw nevig ,esnes edam fo dnik ti tuB
.dluoc eh erehw ecilop eht htiw gnilgnat dediova
.ylluferac liat dna elzzum s’drapoel eht gnivresbo
,ruecarT a fo snoissessop ynam eht fo tuo taht wenk tuaseL tub ,tnemurtsni nrow-llew a saw tI
.ot elba gnieb ton tub ,yalp ot gnitnaw
.em rof dah eh tahw ees ot tnew dna pu I os ,llec ym no egassem a tfel tneilc raluger yM“
,srednuorG eht htiw boj yad sih eunitnoc ot noisiced sih detcepser sruecarT eht fo ynam toN
.ereh teg ot enod dah tuaseL pmuj-llaw eht gnimim ,maiL dias
”?gnihtyreve rof emit tsrif a s’erehT“ ”?ti
”.ssonS ,uoy knahT“
?sredaoleerF ?srotubirtnoC
,htaed laitnetop dna
”.tsol si rof emac ew modeerf yrev eht ,woleb nwod sboj no ekat ew fI
”.syad eseht hcum sa ylraen ni gnimoc t’nera sboj ehT
.remocwen a ylbaborP
liat deppit-kcalb
derewsna ”,tnemevoM ehT tuoba erom tol a wonk ot smees ereh tuaseL dnA
”?ti t'nsi ,ssonS s'ti ,iH“
.sevom sih fo tsdim eht ni ayakS tnorfnoc ot naht retteb wenk eno tub
”.sdrow eseht yb eviL“
.maiL derepsihw ”.sruecarT“
ria fo htrow sroolf evif revo deraos eh sa sdrawpu dekcut swaptoof sih tpek
.mlac yats ot liat sih gnicrof
*** .secafrus etercnoc eht no tfel tac eht skramwalc eht ta gninnirg
etarc dethgiew a tsniaga
,enola su evael spoc ehT
.desurohc sruecarT eht
.ereh saw yrotcudortni sih taht deveiler dekool ssonS
.neht dna won yreve mih sdrawot skool gniworht
”?ees I ,detniauqca gnitteG“
.no yats ot nosaer a meht fo ynam evag dnuorgkcab dna sfeileb rieht derahs taht ytinummoc a gnidniF
.gnikcilf ylerab liat sih
”—ot nrut ot esle eno on evah yeht esuaceb ereh era su fo ynaM“
”?taht od ew dluohs yltcaxe yhW“
.nushA ,thgisni ruoy rof uoy knahT“
,sfeileb sih ni tnangats eb tonnac eno tuB“
.esle enoyreve ot roolf eht ssap won dluow I“
.sevlesmeht gnoma dettahc dna sesicrexe nwod mraw
,dab erew sgniht ,emoh kcaB
htaerb a ekat ot eno rof tniop gnippots laedi na rof edam dah
,stinu noitalitnev mraw owt ssorca detluav-elbuod
”.tnemevoM ehT fo deerc eht htiw gnirehtag s’yadot nigeb lliw I
.gniht emas eht no eerga lla nac ew hcihw ni ylimaf A
,ytinummoc eht morf t'nerew ohw sruecarT fo elpuoc a erew erehT
.ereh si emoH ?erehw naem uoY“
”?thgin fo daed eht ni seireviled seod lleh eht ohW
”.emit tog t’nevaH .oN“
,meht tuoba togrof ylkciuq taht yteicos a ot snoitubirtnoc s’eno etipsed krow syawla t'ndid sgniht tuB
.tevic eht ta kcab ylniatrecnu gnikool ,ssonS
”?niaga yas ,yrros m’I“
.ti rof dewolla gnirehtaG eht ylno fi
ro stinu CA sa hcus serutaef foor on htiw sfoor wef eht fo enO
”?od ew nac esle tahw tuB“
,tnemecalpéd ud tra'L fo selpicnirp yrev eht erew eseht llA
”,enif tsuj ti dootsrednu I“
,deraen eh sa maiL detnemmoc
.evom evisolpxe ylralucitrap a ro sdniw gnorts gnirud neve no yats ot pac eht dewolla os gniod taht wenk
.mih dessessa eh sa dekcilf rae s’arognA ehT
.rehto hcae morf evitcnitsid laudividni yreve dna hcae
.emit tes a yb eunev a ot sdoog eht gnitteg ,rennur dna ecivres reiruoc a neewteb tahwemos denoitcnuf yehT
.ydobyna fo taht yned ot thgir eht sah dlrow eht ni enoyna taht eveileb ton od I
.krow draH dna ecifircaS
,sliat dna swap htiW
.ti tlef maiL dna dehsal liat siH
evom pets-llaw a ffo gniwohs ,meht tsap nar ayakS sa ylhsittiks kcab dekool eH .ssonS derussa
”,won rof mih selttes tahT“
ot elba eb thgim I thguoht dna ,nwod su fo ynam dnib taht sniahc yrev eht yb detcirtser leef I
.llaw gnisoppo eht no desuf ssalg nekorb eht deraelc mub dna seot sih sa eraps ot moor htiw
”!meht tseb ot kees ew
eno fo foor eht ssorca dehsad tuaseL   3 fo 1 traP ,floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“:yojne esaelP
.yllooc diletsum eht ta kcab dekool maiL
.dereffo elytsefil sih llirht dna taews eht retfa mlac eht
.hctaP eht demankcin saw dnuorg gnirehtag eht
gnildnik gninrub htiw deffuts yenmihc dlo na ,ereH
.emit ni ecnetnes eht fo flah tsal eht dehtuom ohw ,esroh wen eht ta ecnalg a tohs tuaseL
.eno ylno eht ton s’eh ,lleW“
,siraP ot mih del dah ytud fo ruot siH
.tuaseL ot txen dils eh sa
enoyrevE  ”.ylimaf lla uoy esuaceB .sgnirehtag rof gnimoc peek I yhw si tahT“ .dekcilf srae s'nushA ”.srehtorb regnuoy pleh dluohs ew ,ylimaf sA
,foor ot foor morf pael ot mih gnirrups ydaerla noitseggus fo rewop eht
.esu doog ot ti tup dluoc ytinummoc dna ylimaf sih taht tnedifnoc saw eh
.delgrug esroh ehT
.yam tahw emoc ot drawno gninnur ,tnemevom sselmaes ni pu kcab deppets eh
.ylesnet tuaseL deksa
.dehgual sruecarT eht dna
.semit ta tluciffid gnidnatsrednu edam
tsehc sih tsniaga dekcut elzzuM
,floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“
s’tuaseL  .sgnidnuorrus ruoy ot ydob s’eno gnitpada fo elpmaxe enif A
.enod eb dluoc gnihton
”?ti fo tuo teg ew od tahW“
,redluohs eht no mih dettap eh sa esroh suovren eht htiw sdrow fo elpuoc a gnignahcxe maiL was tuaseL
eht sa draeh eb dluoc skcarcesiw dna rethguaL
htap a deraelc ylevitceffe eh ,meht gnitcatnoc yllautca tuohtiw stnenoppo hguorht gnihsad yB
.tuaseL dna maiL htiw swap deppirg retto ehT
,yrrauq fo esahc eht ton
?tuoba uoy dlot I boj doof-tsaf eht rof ydaeR ?uoy eraf woh oS“
,tniop sih was tuaseL ”.tsap eht toN
,nopu doots won eh etarc nedoow eht otno depmats eh sa maiL ekops
.sruecarT erew ereht sa snosaer ynam sa rof ot nruter reven dluoc yeht emoh a
,)skooB affaJ yb dehsilbup ylremrof(
.gniwonk ton ffo retteb saw eno seireviled erew yeht
.ruf eht otno gnihctac eugnot ypsar ,wap sih fo kcab eht dekcil tac ehT
.tnemmoc ot edam ayakS sa neve ylkciuq deksa maiL
,eleU“ ,hsilgnE ni rO .isakam abilom é léU .sey ,hO
,doohrobhgien eht dettod taht sgnidliub tnemtrapa yrots-evif ynam fo tuo
.nosrep ni dna efil ni flesym retteb
,mih erofeb pu gnidael sriats leets eht pu eta sedirts s’tevic ehT
.efil ni secneirepxe s’eno ot gniyfitset
.detlit daeh sih sa gnihctiwt sreksihw ,maiL dias
.mih erofeb derehtag esoht ta hteet sih dettirg maiL
”.tnemevoM ehT fo yhposolihp yrev eht tub
,ratiug sih thguorb dah drapoel ehT
,mih no saw thgilerif eht taht woN
.ti ot nwod emac ti fi tser eht fo troppus eht evah dluow maiL taht tbuod t'ndid tevic eht tub ,meht gnoma relwarb tseb eht eb yam ayakS
,dias eh ”,enoyreve ,iH…rrE“
.foor ybraen a nopu gnidnal ,pilf ydob drawrof a htiw ffo dehsinif tuaseL dna maiL  .kcolb siht detneserper tsegnol eht neeb dah maiL ,won rof tub ,saw noitcesretnI ni ruecarT tsrif eht ohw wenk eno oN
,tevic a deniamer eh sa gnol sA
.sgnirehtaG eht morf ruf detnecs-nobruob fo pmul dezisrevo taht dennab t'ndah maiL yhw
,devom eh sa neve erow eh taht trihs dna stnap kcart ekiN eht tsniaga deniarts yllacitcarp
”.dekcehc ev'I emit tsal tsrow eht t’nsaw yaP
,eno on ot degnoleb dnal eht ,ereH
,saw eh teviC nacirfA eht gnilbmeser os elyograg depahs-lesaew eht saw ti rehtehW
,sraey rof noitcesretnI ot gnimoc neeb dah sruecarT ,dootsrednu tuaseL tahw morF
”!tsap gnol fo srotsecna ruo htiw os saw sa
traeh sih otni tperc pmul A
.snur yreviled lareves niater tey dna
,seitic tnereffid neewteb sdoog fo tniop refsnart rojam a erofereht saw dna
.ayakS enirevlow eht saw ti wonk ot dnuor nrut ot dedeen sruecarT eht fo enoN
.noitanitsed s’eno ot teg ot elbissop snaem yna fo esu eht degaruocne tnemevoM ehT
”,deeR ,tup yltcniccuS“
”.su ni dellitsni os dna thguat neeb dah sA“
,yrots nwo rieht dah enoyrevE
,fleseno evorpmi ot ylno demia tnemevoM ehT fo selpicsiD
”!tsap gnol fo srotsecna ruo htiw os saw sa ,tnemevom larutan yna fo elbapac lla era eW“
.fles fo modeerf osla tub ,evom ot modeerf eht tsuj ton si tnemevoM ehT fo elpicnirp yrev ehT“ .tuaseL dias
,llewriats a neve
”,em ot emit fo etsaw ekil sdnuoS“
”,kroY weN morf
.redluohs thgir sih revo dellor eh sa wolb eht gninoihsuc ruf kciht
?niaga ti saw tahW
ssonS ot gninialpxe saw tevic eht sa neve tuaseL sdrawot deklaw tac ehT
,ega s’noocar eht saw eh nehw tlef dah eh woh derebmemer eh sa
ylsuovren decap esroh ehT
.pu kcab tog eh sa tuaseL ot gniddon
”!detrats gniht siht teg s'teL“
.pihs nedalrevo na ni skeew dereffus dna ,nwotemoh sih deugalp tsernu livic retfa depacse ylerab nushA
,siraP fo seueilnab eht ni siob-suos-yhcilC
.won rof no yrrac dluoc eh os
.sgnirehtag owt tsal eht dah eh sa
,etarc eht sdrawot deppets eh sa esroh eht no erew seye llA
”!srehto eht ot klat oG
snoitacilbuP laoG yb
.asiobaM tuaseL m'I“ .tuaseL deksa
,srellewd dnuorg eht ot derettam taht ytic eht fo hcum ees dluoc eh ,noitcesretnI fo gnidliub lapicinum eht pota ereH
elbareferp eb dluow
tuaseL ”.flesti tnemevoM ehT ot wen os ton tub ,ytinummoc siht ot wen m'I .rennaT
tropsnart fo seuneva lla hcihw morf ytic a saw noitcesretnI
.devom eh sa neve tuoba gnihsal liat
”,buc gnissim a rof gnikool era ecilop eht taht stcatnoc ym morf draeh I“
,taht hguorht dnA
”.srehto eht morf yawA
”,tniop a sah nushA kniht I“
.bmilc rieht fo noitrexe eht morf gnitnap ylerab
.meht dnuora esoht naht retteb eb ot ton
.”gnortS yreV si tnerruC eht
.maiL ot gninrut ,tevic eht deksa
.revo s’emag reccos ,thgirlA“
,slennahc tropsnart ynam s'noitcesretnI hguorht stekcar gnilggums rieht detarepo sgnag emoS
.tif flesmih tpek dna ,onimalaP a saw ssonS taht ees dluoc tuaseL
.noitcafsitas htiw swap sih gnibbur ,maiL dias
,woleb nwod llab gniyalp sbuc fo puorg a devresbo eH
.yrotadnam secrof demra eht ni gnivres edam tnemnrevog eht retfa ecnivorp naijuF tfel oahC nilognap eht dna adnap der eht gnihC
,yteicos fo aes eht ni senord erem eb dluow eW
.meht ekil stnargimmi rof dias eb ot gnihtemos saw hcihw
,pael niatrecnu elgnis a htiW
.gnivirra tsuj ylno erew sruecarT eht fo emos taht ees dluoc
,flesmih yojne ot dik a rof deen eht ees t'ndid eh dna
.dehgual tuaseL dna eH
!ssonS rotnem ot gnivah fo tcepsorp eht ta stcaer tuaseL woh tuo dnif ot emit txen
.gnizilaicos dna rennid rof foor deerga-yllautum nwo rieht no teem dluow
,nalp a hcus fo esoprup eht ees ton yam
.deilper noitagergnoc eht
”.deeccus ot yaw rieht no srehto pleh ot deen ew ,ytic eht fo shtap eht ot dnim dna seidob ruo denutta tub evah ew hguohT
.taem tnrub dna lio elats fo knits eht htiw detautcnup seiceps tnereffid ynam os fo stnecs eht yb demlehwrevo neeb syawla dah dna—
.ereht nwod no gniog emag lufrednoW
ytiretxed dna slliks eht htiw enoyna dna sdrib eht evas
,selcatsbo on era erehT“
.lanrutcon a gnieb sa llew sa
.ylimaf rehtona evah ew ,ereh tuB“
.don a htiw ti demrifnoc deeR .oahC dias
.ylimaf dnif yeht
.eh saw os ,regnarts eht htiw enif saw maiL fI .dexaler eh dna
ria nepo eht fo modeerf eht taht enigami dluoc tuaseL dna ,flesti ni aibohportsualc saw ecaps denifnoc a nihtiw gnieb fo thguoht yrev ehT
?yllaer ,ti si lacitcarp woh tub
.dnuora decap maiL sa tnemesacne etercnoc a no dehcrep tuaseL ,retal
ereh tuoyal gnidliub eht fo ytirailimaf eht ro
.dnuorgkcab rieht fo eno rof elbissop efil tseb eht dah sbuc sih taht suoixna
.em ksa uoy fi ,gniht fo tros siht rof detius retteb eb thgim slanrutcon ehT
.ekops yllanif maiL nehw
)moc.yellavtibbar.www//:sptth( sserP yellaV tibbaR yb 0D3%egap62%52D3%rebmun_nruter62%hsarTB2%yrruFD3%txet_hcraesF3%php.hcraesF2%moc.yellavtibbar.wwwF2%F2%A3%sptth=lru_nruter&9089=meti?php.meti/moc.yellavtibbar.www//:sptth  .sserP yellaV tibbaR yb hsarT yrruF dna
esae decitcarp fo sraeY
noinapmoc a saw tI
;seihposolihp lanosrep dna sreffo boj ,tnrael snosseL
,sevo m eht tsuj toN“
.ecafrus gnimmuh eht tsniaga eciwt gnihsup swap
.adnap der eht deksa
.taoc s’onimalaP eht no taews fo neehs a ees dluoc
.traeh emaS“  ”?dnim emaS“
.cra tcefrep a ni drawrof mih gniworht mutnemom sih
.dootsrednu tuaseL  .dehgis maiL
gnorutnib gnitisiv a yb deinapmocca toleco nA
.noitatuper a etiuq dah ayakS wenk enoyrevE
”.sdrow eseht yb eviL“
,nooccar a saw eh wenk tuaseL ,ksam kcalb dna liat depirts sih morF
”—srennuR wollef ,gnineve dooG“
,enola doots eh elihw yalp srehto eht gnihctaw
'sruecarT' sa nwonk tnemevoM ehT fo selpicsid eht ,yad hcaE
,thgirpu tas eh sa mih sdrawot daeh sih dekrej ssonS ”.asiobaM
.ereht reidwor hcum era syug ehT
.nushA drapoel eht dnuora gnicnuob
,dnal wen siht ot devom eh ecnis tol a devorpmi dah hsilgnE siH
.siob-suos yhcilC ni tnemtrapa etar-driht a dewolla ylno saw eh dna
,derettefnu deunitnoc eh ,dnuorg eht tsniaga talf gnidnal swap llA
tsoob a ni ti otno toof a gnimmals
,esiwrehto ro derehtag ,sruecarT lla fo flaheb nO“
eht nehw ylno sruecarT rehto eht
.sevom llaw rof noitcart hcum evig ot gniog erew sfooh eht taht kniht t’ndid
.dlrow eht otni emoc dah ew  hcihw htiw seidob yrev eht htiw
,ytilimuH ,tcepseR
”,ereh cat-cit I emit eht dnuora em raeh yllausu nac uoY“
tuaseL .yad hcae nrael ot wen gnihtemos saw ereht
fo strap #3 fo #1 eht eht saw sihT
.syug eht dna mih yb deggum teg ot tuoba saw eh thguoht eh fi derednow tuaseL
erom hcum os fo elbapac erew yeht derevocsid elpoep nommoc nehw
.rehtegot enoyreve peek ot hcum os enod dah ohw eno ot eud saw hcum taht tub
,rewot gnilooc a morf decnuop adnap der A
,dlo sraey 61 tuobA“
.erom ecno nirg a ni dehsalf sgnaf siH
,rotnem a yb mih ot detrapmi tnemevoM ehT fo selpicnirp eht ylno gnivaH
,egats tfihsekam eht no
no saw eh etarc eht ta ylsuoludercni dekool tac ehT
,boj raluger a tuohtiw tub ,su sevig tnemevoM ehT modeerf eht yojne I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tnemevorpmi-fles tcejer ot si egnahc tcejer ot rof
.rehtegot swap sih deppalc arogna ehT
.derettuts eh sa ynnihw s’esroh eht pu kcip dluoc
.drow thgir eht rof thguof tuaseL ereH
.keew a tuoba rof ereh neeb ev'I“
.srekoolno fo tifeneb eht rof ti did eh fi derednow tuaseL ,tnemom a rof dna
”.siraP morf m'I“ .ecnedifnoc fo kcal s'noillats eht fo sgnivigsim sih kcab gnithgif ,tuaseL deksa
”?he ,erofeb nees ev’uoy ekil gnihtoN
”.hcuot ruoy gnisol era uoy fi rednow ot gnitrats m'I tub ,oN“
,yrots s'maiL wenk eno oN
,sdrow sih dnuof eh sa neve detatiga saw tac ehT
,selcsum dna swap nwo sih dexelf eH
.smra sih dedlof eh sa maiL dias
ygrene pu-tnep taht gniveiler fo snaem a hcum sa saw ti taht detcepsus tuaseL dna ,thgin ta seireviled tneuqerf htiw emocni sih tnemelppus did eH
woleb stik dna sbuc eht ta dekool eH
”.segnellahC ylno ,selcatsbo on era erehT“
”?etam ,erifpmac gnorw eht ot yaw ruoy dnif uoY“
,stoor pu tes dah eh ereht saw ti dna
.neht ecnis devorpmi dah elpoep rieht fo gnivil fo dradnats eht dna ,ytinummoc rieht ni gnivirht saw tnemevoM ehT ,shtnom nihtiW
rebmemer dna ,edirts sih ni tnemnorivne eht ekat dluow eh
,boj eht tnaw uoy fo yna fI“ .ayakS dias
.tnecca kciht sih ni ayakS delward ”!yssup a eb t’noD
.egde s’foor eht no tsam enohpelet dlo na otno ylsselesion gnippirg
mih ekirts ylralucitrap ton did hteet gnikcilc dna seye gnirekcilf ylsuovren eht dna
.sthguoht rieht deohce nushA sa tnelis saw
.teef sih fo sllab eht no kcab decnuob dna dennirg tuaseL
.sboj ni rehto hcae gnitsissa lluf swap ruo evah ydaerla I dna oahC
”?taht tuoba uoy llet maiL did ,tihS“
remocwen eht deksa ”?hcum gniknihT“
,secneirepxe s’yad rieht detnuocer sruecarT
.ytilimuH .tcepseR .ytsenoH
.mih no seye rieht gnirob sruecarT eht ot gnitrad seye
.ecafrus a otno deppirg eh tnemom eht meht gnihtaehsnu ylno
,teef sih ta llab eht htiw sbuc rehto eht hguorht dehsad
,pilf daehrevo na ni tsrif-daeh dednecsed eh sa doow dekram-walc eht ffo yltnelis deleep eH
dessim reve I evah nehW“
.emitemos llabtoof yrt dluohs uoY !nuf s’tI“
,dednal nworb fo hsalf a sa prihc a htiw detautcnup saw teef fo rettap a ,tsartnoc nI
.ti ot yltnatsnoc mih werd tops siht tuoba gnihtemoS
”,enod eb ot si gniniart hcus erofeb sutats tnerruc ruo redisnocer llahs ew nehT“  ”.ti rof m’I
,ti ffo toof lufrewop eno gnihcnub
.ecilop yb sehcraes roirp tneverp ot snaem xodohtro ssel yb dereviled erew sdoog niatrec dna
/flowisakim/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:sptth floWisakiM/ikiw/moc.rufikiw.ne//:sptth egap ytiniffaruF ro rufikiW sih no seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoy dna
ni deraeppa ylremrof dah ”drawroF paeL A“
,dniheb esolc dewollof
.dniheb sdnoces owt gniwollof dneirf siomahc sih
,yawa demmar eb ton sa os yawa yats dluow sbuC
”.ysuol si hsilgnE ym ,yrroS“ .tuaseL deifiralc ”,tirips emaS
,sretsis dna srehtorb elttiL
,alagniL ni drapoel eht deteerg tuaseL ”,nushA ,yeH“
,mih detlusni ohw syug owt fo swaj eht gnikaerb mih was rab eht ta thgin A
.tuoba uoy ot klat ot deen I gnihtemos s'erehT .tuaseL ,emoC“
.raey a flah rof ereh neeb ylno gnivah etipsed seirots s'ruecarT eht fo eno yreve wenk tuaseL
,deraperpnu dna yrawnu eht ot dnik reven erew seueilnab ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.deedni remocwen A
”.ruoh eht ton ,boj eht yb diap er’eW
”,dlo emas ,dlo emas ,hO“
.ria eht decreip lworg a dna lrans a neewteb ssorc a sa
.sdrow sih dnuof eh sa gnislup dna gnitcartnoc selcsum taorht sih
”?he ,sgnidliub eht ot koot uoy nehw ytinummoc foor eht tuoba tuo dnuoF“ .delims tuaseL ylsuovren dehgual eH
tuaseL ,thgil gnimmid eht etipseD
.sdrawpu meht werd tnemevoM ehT fo tsriht
”?esle gnihtyna ereht sI .neht ,thgirlA“
,ereh tub—“
”?em deppots taht sah nehW“
”?swollef sih htiw erahs ot ekil dluow yeht gnihtyna evah enoyna seoD
.dleif yhctap eht ssorca deyenruoj ti sa llab eht gniwollof daeh sih
.seye sih fo setihw eht gnitautnecca
.tnemevoM ehT fo tcepsa degaruocne na t'nsaw ffo gniwohs yhw
”!sevlesruo tub enoyna ot gnihton evorp eW
tuaseL .noisiv s’tuaseL fo edis eht otni wodahs a tsac arognA hsitirB eht fo tlep etalocohc yklis ehT
.sfeileb rieht htiw detsurt eb t'ndluoc eh taht hcus ,dedne-elbuod
.sruecarT eht detelpmoc
tuaseL .ni ecnedifnoc elttil dah yeht sevom yna mrofrep ot desoppus t’nerew sruecarT .ngis doog a toN
,eurt eb ot traeh s’eno morf emoc tsum sgnos ehT
.hguoht ,seiceps fo noitnem oN
.su erofeb dah srehto tahw ylno gniveihca
tey dna ,repeeklaog a sa detius retteb eb dluow ezis sih fo yug A
tuaseL .ylbatrofmoc tif ot selohrae eht yfidom ot dah eh taht hcus ,kcab ot tnorf pac srekcoD neerg-ikahk sih erow syawla tac eht
,dnuorg eht otno kcab llef sgel sih sa
.dereffo sfoor nepo eht
,diletsum egral eht morf detaname stirips detrossa fo ecnegnup ehT
.meht ot nwonk saw sa srednuorG ro
tuoba tnrael ereh enoyreve tsoM .gnirehtaG eht gnirud uoy tuoba tuo dnuof tsuj ylno ev'I“ .daeh sih koohs tuaseL  .did eh sa gniralf slirtson ,derettuts eH
egde eht ta elyograg eht dnuof tuaseL
.detcefrep dah yeht sevom eht gnimim meht fo emos
.sruecarT fo seuqilc tnereffid eht gnoma ylniatrecnu gnikool
”,ylrae krow ffo er’uoY“
.ecalp tsrif eht ni emoh kcab snoitidnoc diova ot ereh emac sruecarT eht fo ynaM
,emoh morf raf dnal egnarts a ni devirra yeht nehw enola osla saw enoyreve tub
tuaseL .htrof tup retto eht
,era ew ohw su ekam taht sevles euqinu eht eb reven nac ew ,ti tuohtiW“
,pu nar knim eht iksurK
.leef I yaw eht dnatsrednu ohw srehto era ereht taht dezilaer I dna ,neht dna won yreve daehrevo gnissap syug uoy nees ev'I—I
.ylsuovren dehgien eh ”.ma I ereh oS
”?maiL ,tuoba siht s’tahW“
,hsul sih no dniw eht tsniaga ylsseltroffe delioc selcsum lufrewop dna ywenis
,sfooh fo kcalc yrotangis a htiw teparap eht no dednal-noisicerp taog niatnuom A
?ees ,si reve ylimaf on tub ,tcefrep ton si tI
,maiL deunitnoc ”,noitseggus siht no evah yam enoyna sweiv yna raeh ot ekil erofereht dluow I“
.emac dniw eht nehw raegdaeh demmirb rieht tsol srennigeb ynam ooT
,gnihsaw-wodniw t’nsaw eh nehw seireviled tnemucod enod dah
.llor a ni gnilbmut
.enola tfel gnieb ffo retteb erew ecilop eht htiw skcehc dnuorgkcab dna sDI
.keew eht fo dne eht ta edulcnoc dna ,emit txen eunitnoc lliw hcihw ,strap eerht ni yrots a si sihT
.gnikcilf enam sih fo skcol eht
,mih ta ylgnivorppasid dekool maiL
su fo emos hguoht roF“
,sllaw ruof nihtiw pu depooc yad eht fo sruoh enin gnidneps enigami t’ndluoc eh tub
tnemevoM ehT fo tiripS eht si ti roF .gnihton era ew ,selpicnirp ruo tuohtiW
.derocs raeb eht sa delwoh woleb sbuc ehT ”?ti deyalp revE
”.yug wen eht rotnem ot uoy ekil dluow I“
.devirra sruecarT eht fo eroM
tlas sih htrow tnargimmi nA
.dewols ratiug sih fo gnimmurts eht dna ,tnemom a rof thguoht nushA
,seitilanosrep tnereffid sseltnuoc fo seicnaf dna smihw eht reffus ot gnivah
.ti pota dehcrep dna
fo nwotemoh dlo sih fo taht ot
.ruf sih delffur ezeerb emoclew a sa ylwols gnivaeh tsehc
;maiL deivne
”?tuaseL ,siht no sthguoht yna evah uoY
.sruecarT eht fo sreehc eht ot ecafrus nedoow eht fo pot no depmolc eh
ytiC noitcesretnI ot yaw sih edam eh woh dna
tuaseL ,edirts tpek eh sa drawrof dehcterts swaP
,saw eh erehw ot teg ot stnemevom emas eht yllacitcarp hguorht gniog etipseD ”?ti saw woH“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,stluav ro snur llaw gnimrofrep nehw detcarter swalc sih tpek eH
.dniheb evael ew esoht tuoba kniht ot tluciffid s’ti htnom tsrif eht roF
.gnidliub txen eht ot revo mih gnignirps
,edis eht ot ylbatrofmocnu gnittis ssonS was tuaseL
.flesmih rof erom thguorb dah eh detseggus kcap gnittif-mrof sih fo gniknilc eht dna
.demrof saw noitanitsed s’eno no noisiced a sa neve
.nwo ym fo sgnos sti sselnu meht yalp ot elba eb t'now I tuB
.drow tsal eht dezisahpme maiL
?tcaf taht yned yllaer dluoc doohrobhgien eht ni ynam woh dnA
semit sseltnuoc stnioj doof tsaf edisni neeb dah
,enam sih fo ssot a htiw pu tog eh tub
!taht naht ti ot erom s’ereht yleruS“
,sruecarT deliat-egral lla ekiL
”!ydobyreve ,ereh uoy evah ot taerG“ ”-ees uoy ,lleW“
,saw ydaerla ti naht erom yna hsal t’ndid liat siH
.wap fo evaw a htiw maiL dias
.eciov peed a delward
.htiw ygrene sih hctam ot esle enoemos rof dnuora ylevitruf gnikool ,deklus iksurK dna ,sevom sih hctam ot secnetsisni sih ffo devaw drapoel ehT
”.srehto rotnem ot ekil si ti tahw wonk lliw ew
.dah eh naht regnol tnemnorivne dna tnemevoM ehT ot demotsucca neeb dah eh tuB
.teef sih ot tog dna swap koohs yeht sa gnisrepsid
.dnuora gnitteg fo tra eht
ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,dehca selcsum siH
.emit fo tniop emos ta evah lla eW“ .deddon nushA
.hctaw dluow ohw esle enoyna dna iksurK fo tifeneb eht rof
tnemevom ysae ,diulf a ni etarc eht ffo dils maiL
.detrons sruecarT ehT
.tcaf taht fo meht dnimer ot suoixna oot lla saw ayakS dna ,srepmuj tnellecxe erew senirevlow ,ezis rieht etipseD
.derusaert tsom eht fo eno saw tnemurtsni lacisum a
”?emoh gninruter deredisnoc reve uoy dah ,nushA“
.maiL detnecs eh sa gnihctiwt eson ,tuaseL dias
tuaseL dna ,htrof dna kcab yaws ot gnitrats saw liat sih ydaerlA
.ecnalg a naht erom esroh eht deraps ydobon tub
,sevlesmeht gnoma deklat srehto eht sa yb ylsuovren doots ohw esroh railimafnu na ees dluoc tuaseL
.enut sih otni kcab desum nushA dna ,tuaseL deilper
htiw emac taht ecnadiug eht ylpmis saw taht tub ,sdrawot gninnur saw eh tahw aedi on dah eH
.gnihctiwt sreksihw sih ,maiL deksa
.enola noisluper lacigolohcysp hguorht
”.egnahc tpecca ot noisiced eht gnikam si modeerf ,semitemoS“
.ti hguorht llaf sih fo ecrof eht gninetfos
.slennahc lamron eht hguorht
,foor tnecajda na fo llewriats eht ffo decnuob ruf nworb dna kcalb
tluav waprevo na htiw delpuoc hsad A
,tnemevom larutan yna fo elbapac lla era eW“
”!revo gnirehtaG eht eralced I ,ton fI“
enoemos rof dnuora ylkciuq dekool eH
.ezeerb gnineve looc eht tlef yeht sa ylwols gnihtaerb
.suoivne eb ot nosaer on dah tevic eht tub ,tac a gnieb ot segatnavda erew erehT
ecnesse yrev eht si ytilaudividni taht rednuoF eht fo sdrow eht morf wonk lla eW“
,dnuorg eht no boj a dekrow yllautca ohw sruecarT wef eht fo eno saw nushA .emit yna
;noitacilppa boj htiw detaicossa secneinevnocni eht wenk enoyrevE
.noitnem ot detcelgen eh ytic a ni toped sub eht ta dekrow ayakS
.ti fo ytiludercni eht ta delims tsomla tuaseL dna
.meht dnif ot kees ew ,sgniw tuohtiW“  ”!segnellahC ylno
efasnu ro lacitcarpmi eb esiwrehto dluow taht seireviled hguorht ylniam gnivil rieht edam tnemevoM ehT fo selpicsiD
,daeherof nedlog keels sih revo deppird dna detserc enam tpmeknu ,kcalb A
.drawkcab ton ,drawrof knihT
.iksurK derettum ”.flesruoy rof kaepS“
.sruecarT rehto eht htiw gnola raegdaeh sih ffo nekat dah eH .maiL ekops
,esahc eht ot llirht niatrec a saw erehT .wolF eht
htiw no deirrac gnirehtag eht pu tes ot gnipleh ton esohT
.rotarepo evaus a sa
,no saw gnirehtaG eht sa gnol sa tub ,ayakS ta slwocs werht sruecarT eht fo tser ehT
.won dna ereh eht fo kniht uoy ,erehwemos evirra uoy nehW
,drawrof deppilf dna rab gnignahrevo na otno deppirg eh sa tuo deppilf swalC
”,hguone riaF“ ”?ton ti si
ssonS m'I .sruecarT wollef ,gnineve doog ,lleW .yrroS !hO“
taht tsuj eb ot demees yretae yreve ,ereh—
emit htneetpmu eht rof derednow
,noos dna ,mih ta deggan noitseuq a tub ,gniyalp nushA ot denetsil dna tsehc sih tsniaga teef sih dekcut eH
.sevlesmeht rof si ereht emit hsac revetahw ecifircas ot
setatS detinU eht ni ytilacol dna noitisop s'noitcesretnI
.denethgit waj s’tuaseL
.noitucesorp gnidulcni snosaer rof semoh suoiverp rieht tfel gnivah tsom
,)ne=gnal?flowisakim/moc.rettiwt//:sptth(  floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“
.seson rieht delknirw sruecarT ybraen
,ytsenoH fo selpicnirp eht yb evil eW“
gnithgil saw eh erifpmac eht morf kcab decnalg maiL
,seniledis eht yb buc a was eh sa derevaw elims
,tae ot hguone dah yehT
,evisnetni ,hsrah saw gniniart siH
.nosaer tuohtiw ton
.gnidliub hsiyerg a pota thgir dednal dna
.tnemevoM ehT tuoba wenk eh tahw fo tsom nos sih thguat eh nehw selpicnirp owt tsal eht ylno gniulav rehtaF taht derebmemer tuaseL .tnemevoM ehT ti dellac selpicsid sti ,emit revO
.drapoel eht nageb
,elgna na ta llewriats a fo llaw eht sdrawot gnurps eH
.tsaf ti nrael ot dah srehtorb eht taht lavivrus nwo rieht rof saw ti dna
.etercnoc eht ssorca gnippolc sfooh
.ylgnidnatsrednu deddon maiL
.dehctiwt eson s'tuaseL
,euqinhcet sih ot noitcart niatrec a evag teef ralucsum ,dewalc siH
.esirnus erofeb enod eb ot sah ti
.rehtorb regnuoy sih ot ralimis ylgnikirts gnikool
.detegdif ohw drapoel eht ot denrut tac ehT
”,morf ylsuoiverp erew uoy erehw ot kcab tnaem I ,oN“
”.rehtaf dna srehtorb redlo ruo rof hcum os toN
,htiw railimaf erom saw drapoel eht eugnot a otni kcab dehctiws tuaseL
”?nushA .nekat tnioP“
,rettam taht rof ,tey selamef rehto yna ro ,ytinummoc ruecarT rieht ni seram on erew ereht tuB
.dnuora deltsoj eb ot sdoof fo tseb eht t’nerew azzip dna seldooN
nehW“ .thgilerif eht ni gnihsalf sgnaf ,dennirg nushA
.mih sdrawot yaw sih edam os
”!toocs ,no oG“ .swap sih pu werht maiL
,mih decudortni evah thgim ohw
.noisufnoc ni desaerc deworb dettesor sih sa dehctiwt sreksihw siH ”.spotfoor nO
.luof a htiw degrahc eb ton dluow raeb eht tub
tuaseL .doof fo ecnereferp laudividni nwo rieht htiw hcae
.semoh rieht emaceb sfoor eht dna ,sruecarT tsom rof lacitcarpmi gnivil dnuorg edam dah tner dna gnivil fo tsoc ehT
ypoc drah ni deriuqer stnemhsilbatse etavirp dna eciffo gnippihs eht taht sredro refsnart dengis ro stsefinam tnegru erew yeht yllausU
,emit eht fo flah tub ,sdoog rieht revo gnidnah nehw
fo pmul dezisrevo nA
.ydotsuc ecilop morf delf
.syaw ruo ecarbme ot yticapac eht srehto evig lliw ti
,gnirehtaG eht sa nwonk rehtegot-teg a eb dluow ereht ,keew a ecno dnA
.gnisaerc ksam laicaf sih ,mih ot denrut
.efil ruo si tnemevoM ehT“
.deilper sruecarT detaes eht ”!ssonS ,iH“
.wob detareggaxe na htiw trapretnuoc reggib sih ot txen ylsselesion dednal tub ,pilf eno ylno ni dedeeccus ,netram a
,etinarg tsniaga mined fo edils eht draeh ylerab tuaseL
.yaw rehto yna ti evah t’ndluow I dna ,em htiw gnola emac slliks yM .ereh emac I os
stnemtimmoc sih edam ti taht tlef yehT
seugnot rieht dna stac htiw od ot dah hcihw esarhp naciremA na llacer ot gnitrats saw tuaseL
.tuoekat nailatI dna esenihC eht htiw stnedicni eht ecnis reve sboj yreviled doof lla revo dessap dah tub
,esae ta tlef eh ereh tuB .ton wenk eh
,tirips dna gnos s’eno fo rekovni dna
”...emas eht fo lla era ew tub
?yllaer ew era ohw
,dednal diletsum eht sa delworg tuaseL .pmuj-
.ecnalab rof eciwt gnihsal
did leciC nos rehto sih dna tuaseL gnirusne ydaerla
tnew gnihtyreve
yrotciV ot yaW eht walC
.nekops saw deerc eht emit hcae mih hguorht deslup taht
,dnoyeb dna tnenitnoc naciremA htroN eht fo tser eht ot del
tuaseL .esiwrehto ro ticilli
,ecalp emas eht morf ton era eW
.pmuht a htiw gnidnal erofeb ria eht ni eciwt gnippilf
,yroeht ni doog dna llew yrev sdnuos pihsrotnem tuoba klat taht llA“
,ylsuoiraorpu dehgual ayakS
,woleb secaps ytinummoc dna sgnidliub esir-wol fo dleif eht
”.smees ti tahw etiuq ton s'ytic ehT
,teparap eht fo pot no toof a demmals eh ,pord a fo egde eht ta thgiR .ruf dettops
,niluaprat sti morf tuo etarc ytpme na deggard tuaseL sA
.sseug s'enoyna saw
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.loohcs tfel I erofeb ti yalp ot desu I
.sevlesmeht gnoma gniklat detrats srehto eht sa
.pu seirots neves neve elbidua seirc rieht
.secafrus etercnoc gnitcatnoc morf nettog evah dluohs yeht sa nrow ylerab erew esroh eht fo spitfooh looc eht taht leef dluoc tuaseL ,sdap desuollac hguorht neve dna ,wap s'tuaseL koohs ylregnig noillats ehT .syug eht fo emos htiw gnittahc saw ohw maiL ot detrad seye sih sa yldetatiga gnikcilf srae
”.roolf eht ekat dluohs uoy spahrep ,ssonS“
eht sa enirevlow eht dewolleb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
?raf os ytinummoc eht gnidnif uoy era woh oS“
,hctaP eht otno derebmalc
tuaseL .ffo dehsad dna eugnot sih tuo kcuts maiL
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.buc a saw eh nehw mih thguat dah rehtom sih ognoC eht morf gnos lanoitidart a ekil dednuos tI
.dehctiwt liat yffulf sih sa opmet a tuo gnitaeb
”?gnirehtaG eht ot em htiw gnimoC
”?sevlesruo thguat ew sevom yrev eht srehto hcaet ew taht gnitseggus uoy erA“
,eueilnab a fo strap reroop eht ni devil uoy nehw tnatropmi saw regnad morf yawa gnitteG
modeerf eht rof esahc eht tub
.nirg a ni dehctiwt sreksihw
.t’nevah uoy ekil smeeS“
.nur ot hguone doog erew yeht nehw sessoB lacol eht rof sboj
.won rof prahs kool enoyreve tseB
raeb nworb a sa sgnisum suoiverp sih morf dezingocer tuaseL mohw tsegral ehT
.enoyreve rof yalp lliw I ,tnemurtsni na evah I
.siraP fo sottehg eht
.noitseuq eht gnisop fo raef eht edorrevo ytirailimaf larutluc
stcartnoc htiw deipucco esoht fo stseretni tseb eht ni eb t’ndluow tI
.htiw deubmi ro nrob neeb dah yeht
esiwrehto ro sruecarT ,elpoep eht fo smsimehpue eht fo emos tub
,snaej dna tsev strops regnezalS a gninnoD
,tniop gniteem rieht ot revo dial sdraobroolf eht revo deklaw yehT
,kcaba nekat dekool ssonS
.spil sih ot resiewduB fo elttob a detfil eh sa ayakS deksa
,gniunitnoc erofeb tac eht ta denediw seye ’ssonS
.tuaseL ta kcab dekool nushA
.dnuorg drah no sdap fo duht tniaf a yb dewollof
.emit a ta eerht revo gnicnad yllacitcarp
”?flesruoy ecudortni ot ekil uoy dluow ,ssonS
.stniartsnoc ecaps yna tuohtiw dnuora tuo hcterts dluoc sruecarT eht erifpmac yna sa llew sa dekrow
.retirw yranecreM floW a si ohw
deliocnu selcsum siH
.maiL dias ”.ffuts lagelli reviled ot sehsiw ohw esohT“
.tnerehoc ssel on saw tub ,noitcesretnI ni tneps sraey retfa tsaoC tsaE eht fo taht htiw degnit saw tnecca renodnoL siH
.thgir ot tfel morf detrad seye sih sa neve gnikcilc hteet sih ,ssonS dias
tuaseL  drawrof wap dehcnelc a gnuws maiL
.cilbup ni tuo ton nehw ekops emoh kcab ylimaf sih egaugnal eht
m'I“
.suovren dekool iksurK ecnatniauqca sih neve dna
!rotisiv a evah ew ,yadot dnA
.yhw swonk doG ,ereh reccos ti llac yehT
.ti rof esu retteb a dnuof raeb eht
.devivrus seegufer eht fo flah naht sseL
,dednecsed ssonS sa neve noitom tfiws a ni etarc eht no pu tpael eH .maiL dias
,elpoep su sekam taht
.deunitnoc eh ”,tnemecalpéd ud tra'L fo
kcab sraey ytriht nwod dial tnemevoM ehT fo rehtaf eht selpicnirp gnidiug yrev eht erew esohT“
.ytinummoc etaidemmi eht fo tser eht rof evah yam yeht tnemegaruocne dna sthguoht nwo rieht erahs dluow enoyreve hcihw ni
.htaerb a tuo tel maiL
.hcum taews ot demees reven maiL
.ylprahs maiL dednimer ”,ayakS ,tcepseR“
?wonk uoy ,noitats sub eht raen ffo pord ot desoppus m’I epolevne delaes a ni stnemucod fo maer a tsuJ
,sevlesmeht detneserp taht selcatsbo lla ssorca ylsseltroffe dednuob tac eht
,noinapmoc s'enirevlow ehT
.krow draH .ecifircaS
.yrtnuoC dlO eht ni kcab pu dengis dah dna ,noigeL ngieroF saw rehtaF
.gnieb-llew s’eno ot evitcurtsnoc saw ti sa gnol sa
.dnuora teg ew snaem dna syaw eht ylerem ton
”.niaga su rof yalp dluoc uoy taht doog s’tI“
.erofeb mih ot nekops reven dah tub ,ytinummoc rieht nihtiw morf ton raluger a sa mih wenk
,delbmut eh sa liat sih denettalf retto eht
.emoclew erew tnemevoM ehT fo yhposolihp eht dewollof ohw lla tub
,level rewol a ot nwod ydob depirts dna dettops sih werht eh sa neve
,klaw a ot flesmih gniwols yllaniF
.nattahnaM ni srehtegot-teg eht ekilnu yletinifed s’tI“
.yaw doog a ni tub
.desirprus dekool ssonS
”?morf uoy er'erehw ,oS“
”,noitats sub eht ta revo sorb sih fo emos ot ssap teercsid a ekam ot syug fo elpuoc a sdeen eh syas kcilS ytriD ,ay hO“ ”.tluciffid efil ekam nac yeht tub