,luof deirc spoc eht erofeb nwod slevel owt txen eht ot ti ekam dna rood eht tuo kcab dluoc eh wenk ssonS ?spoc eht tub
sbuc rehto eht dna em decnivnoc relykS“ ”-tub ,seY“
”?he ,modeerf ekil gnihtoN“
.rotnem remrof sih rof regna on saw ereht dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.mih ediug ot dedeen eh rehtorb eht sa tuaseL htiw
,ti delransne dah taht sfoor eht fo spot eht morf tuo dekeep nus gninrom ehT
,egaruoc dna ecnedifnoc erup saw tac ehT
,yhposolihp eht hguorht ,dnA
”.esle erehwyna teg ot tnaw yeht fi og ot evah srekroY weN ecalp tsrif eht s’ti ekil ton s’tI
:detnirp saw ti nopU
fo lanif dna driht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.htiw gnilaed erew yeht stcepsus eht fo seitilauq eht gniredisnoc eno tluciffid a
tuaseL *** .hcum oot lla saw ti
.mih ees retteb ot denworf yeht sa ,seye sih ffo detcelfer saw ereht thgil elttil tahW
.mih ta tuo kcurts reciffo suolaezrevo na sa edis eht ot gnihcnilf ,smlap dna teef sih ot deppord ssonS
.efas erew yeht litnu ytilibisnopser sih llits saw ssonS tub ,truh ydob elohw siH
.ecnailpmoc rof delley yeht sa tuo snotab cipocselet dna skcitsthgin
,niaga su htiw nur dluoc eh dehsiw eh semit erew ereht em dlot maiL
.yad eht ton saw yadot tub ,gniniart dna raeg gninnureerF ni tuo dekced
,ti hcaer ot edam eb ot dah taht pmuj gnol eht fo esuaceb ereh emac ylerar sruecarT nevE
.tnemevoM ehT fo selpicnirp eht fo eno ,ytsenoh ylnO
dna kcab keew a ffo nar eH
,rehto hcae morf detrap yeht sa dneirflrig sih ot elims tsal eno evig maiL dehctaw eH
,)skooB affaJ yb dehsilbup ylremrof( snoitacilbuP laoG yb yrotciV ot yaW eht walC ni deraeppa ylremrof dah ”drawroF paeL A“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.spoc eht epacse ot dib a ni niart gnivom a fo pot eht ffo tpael ssonS dna tuaseL ,emit tsaL ]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[   /flowisakim/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:sptth floWisakiM/ikiw/moc.rufikiw.ne//:sptth
.dne rehto eht hguorht tuo gnitnirps erofeb
elpoep lla fo maiL dna
,noitatropsnart cilbup detah syawla dah maiL
uoy evaH ?raf os gniod uoy era woH
.naidraug sih htiw devil ssonS sa gnol sa stnemllatsni ylhtnom ni diap eb ot saw ti dna
,dah reve ti naht esrow truh liat siH
”,oga shtnom 4 deid stnerap 'ssonS“ .tsrif
.gnidliub eht fo senifnoc eht otni gniraeppasid
ylivaeh dehtaerb dna
enoemos dedeen eH
.rossecederp sih fo etaf eht tem evah ot ton hguone etanutrof saw eh tub
nemwal detsagrebbalf eht ot yllacitegolopa dewob ssonS
.retirw yranecreM floW a si ohw
,yawa gninnur ylpmis naht erom saw efil taht nrael dluow ssonS
,llec sih rewsna ot tiderc diaperp hguone dah llits maiL ,yletanutroF
.efil rieht ni esoprup taht
tuaseL deksa ”?kroY weN morf yaw eht lla mih kcart ecilop eht did woh tuB“
.em hctac meht tel reve t’now I“ .denaom ssonS
demees eh ,fooh dekcarc sih dna
.tnereffid saw yenruoj s'nosrep hcae dna ,slaog tnereffid
.ecnatirehni eht rof ni mih koot ylno ehs taht si
.gninetsil saw tuaseL taht won reidaets emaceb eciov siH .maiL dias
.snoitseuq yna diova ot hguone llew diap eh tub
?wonk uoy ,ereht nwod suoregnad s’tI .neppah taht tel reve I fi denmad eb ll'I dnA
,tserra diova ot yhcilC tfel dah tuaseL sa tsuJ
.taorht sih deraelc
eht saw sihT.tnemecalpsiD fo
tuaseL .enif eb ot
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.ega taht ta ecneulfni ot era yeht elbarenluv woh wonk uoy dna ,neetxis ylno s'dik ehT
”,tihsllub si taht fo lla wonk I won tub
,hcuoc sih tsniaga kcab yal dna rewot retaw desusid a otni deppets esroh eht sa nevE
.yella na deraelc eh sa elif delaes-ytiruces eht ffo gnippord
.nialpxe ot epahs yna ni yldrah saw ssonS tub ,erac sih rednu tsurht saw ohw eh retfa erew ecilop eht yhw wonk ot ekil dluow eH
.htiw tnetnoc ot eivom a fo tuo thgir tnua ydeerg a dah yeht ,woN
,syella eht ni thgin hguor a fo elat-llat rieht detpecca dah revird eht dna ,etis noitcurtsnoc eht fo sriats eht nwod yaw sih gnikam retfa
.pu kcab ylhtooms gnidnal
.niks sih hguorht enog evah ot deraeppa ti dna
ssonS rof bac a dellac dah eH
,evil ot si evom ot dnA
morf letni no desab ecalp eht tuo dekats ylbaborp dah spoc eht taht wenk eH
,yreviled sih fo tniop ffo-pord eht dehcaer eH
.hcnuh a fo erus eb ot dedeen tuaseL dna
.emit fo ecaps trohs a hcus ni deneppah hcum oS
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.seruliaf dna sesseccus htob morf nrael ot gnihtemos syawla saw ereht tub
laitnetop lluf sih ot evil ot woh mih wohs ot evah ew
.mih emalb t'ndid tuaseL dnA
.erised nommoc a yb rehtegot thguorb lla
.taht em llac ot ton uoy dlot ev'I .ssonS ,no emoC“
,yadot retnec ytic eht gnitisiv eb yam eh taht denoitnem dah maiL
.mih gnimlehwrevo tsap gnol fo seiromem
lotsip eht no rehtegot gnimoc sfoohtoof
.tcnitsni dnoces a ekil saw ti hguorht stiucric sseltnuoc gninnur morf
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.mih ot denrut srae
trA eht gniwollof fo trap ylpmis saw taht tub
.htap rehtona ot setag erem secnef
.denaorg dne rehto eht ta eciov ehT
:rednuof eht fo sdrow eht ni sA
,dednal ssonS erofeb thgir ruf dna liat fo ssem a ni delbmut netram eht
”?ekil kool yeht od tahW“
,su htiw sgnilaed esaec lliw stneilc ruO
,erutpac-raen morf mih devas rotnem sih ecnis revE
.srehctaw yna esufnoc ot snrut dna stluav eslaf wef a ni gniworht
tuaseL .gnihctiwt srae nworb egral sih
,pu kcab daeh sih gnippanS
.dimit nialp tsuj saw eh thguoht I dna ,laref
.steerts tilnu eht no erutangis a ylerab tlep etalocohc krad sih
?he ,mih tuoba hguone tuB“
sfoohdnah sih no drawrof deraer ssonS
.mih woleb gninepo egde eht fo pord eht
fo tros a tfarc ot mih dewolla gnidliub eht morf skcas liam dlo eht fo emoS
.nwod eid sgniht llit sreppoc eht diova dna
”?taht kniht uoy sekam tahW“
,gnissap rieht retfa mih fo erac ekat ot saw reveohw rof dnuf tsurt a tfel stnerap siH“
.dekrow llits ti desirprus saw eh dna
.kcab sraey owt dah yeht sa yltcaxe tnaegres eht no dekcol seye sih
kcab sih fo llams eht nihtiw decalp elif ehT
delaes erew snoisiced tnatropmi dna ,demriffaer erew sesimorp ,yad wen a
,dleif eht gnideeser nees eb dluoc renedrag tibbar enol a dna ,emag llabtoof a rof ylrae oot saw tI
tuaseL .tevic eht deksa ssonS ”?pu s'tahw ,oS“
,foor sih ot kcab yaw sih edam esroh ehT
.emac ti nehw egnahc gnicarbme dna gnicaf tub
. .netram eht dehcaorppa eh sa
.mih ot emac ti taht naeco na gnissorc retfa ylno saw ti dna
ssonS .oot rehtorb gib a tub tuaseL ,rotnem a eb ot uoy gniksa tsuj ton m'I
.dnuoba snossel dna seitinutroppo fo ezam a saw ti ,stniopyaw dna ,setuor
.ytic gnivlove-reve eht fo
”?tuoba deirrow er'uoy gnihtemos ereht sI“
”.efil si tnemevoM rof
?taht eveileb uoy lliw ,tcirtsid skcod eht ni tuo ti hguor ot gniyrt mih dnuof I
.erom on em hctac ot nosaer yna tog t'nia spoc eht snaem tahT
.dnuorg nevenu eht no yllufniap yal eh sa
.ot elba eb ton yam eh
,mih dnuora ecaps nepo fo stol ot desu saw ohw eno ot modeerf elttil evag tI
.flesmih ot yltfos gnimmuh
,efil rieht ni esoprup thguos meht fo llA
.yadot thguac eb t'ndluow eh tub
,yllaudarg dna ylwols ssonS detfil
.saw efil sih etanutrof woh tsuj dezilaer esroh eht
,rehto hcae sdnatsrednu taht ytinummoc a evah ton yam yeht ,mih tuohtiW
,enog saw eh ,eye na fo knilb a nI
.erac sih rednu esroh eht tuoba dluoc eh lla mih dlot dah maiL wenk tuaseL dna ,enot sih ni ycnegru saw erehT
.si ti tahw rettam on ,gnihtyna tuoba em ot klat syawla nac uoy wonk uoY“
.gnitcefrep efil sih tneps dah eh gnihtyreve pu evig ot
,drawrof devom tuaseL ,pael a htiw dnA
,wols ot raeppa was eh gnihtyreve edam gniniart tnatsnoc fo sraeY
,sekatsim edam tra eht ta sretsam nevE
detroper gnicnerefer-ssorc
,degguh elamef eht dna eH
.dab ro doog saw taht fi wonk t'ndid eh dna ,dnim sih hguorht gnicar erew sthguoht fo sdnik llA
.noitats niart niam eht ot resolc tliub saw eno rewen eht litnu eciffo tsop eht eb ot desu sihT
,niaga taht ekil gnihtyna deirt eh fi tlep sih evah dluow seroleD
,mih ediug ot ydobemos tuohtiw saw ssonS
,luftneve saw erus yreviled s’yadoT
.egarag gnikrap eht fo liated yreve ni gnikat seye
esroh ehT  .rettam on tub
,evol sih htiw eb ot
.dneirfyob reh ot dias ehs gnihtyreve draehrevo ssonS
.oot meht sah kroY weN ,lleW“
,sevawria ecilop eht no eb dluow taht rettahc oidar eht raeh tsomla dluoc eH
eetnem htob hctap depleh tac eht retfa seno retrohs fo seires a gnikoolrevo foor delit a no tas meht fo owt ehT
.”melborP edispoT ehT“
s'tuaseL ”.eno doog a s’ti erus ekaM
.klawedis eht ssorca ecnad a fo reggaws reh ni koot eh sa deltsihw tuaseL
”.rehtaf a emaceb eh ecnis reve
truh evah dluow ti hcum woh wenk tevic eht dna
.shtnom xis tsap eht ni dah eh naht yad eno tsal eht ni erom denrael dah eh
,ti hguorht depees dah doolb fo elkcirt a ydaerlA
”.fo erac ekat ot deen I ffuts tog ev’I
,denepo ybbol niam eht ot rood ssalg ehT .reh ot ekops eh sa gnihgual neve
.em fo ydotsuc sah regnol on tnua ym ,won morf htnom a neethgie nrut I tnemom ehT .evah eruS“
”!llor a ot gnippord tuohtiw hgih taht dnal ot naht retteb wonk uoY
.dniheb esolc dewollof evoba efil elihw ,drawrof devom woleb efiL
.ti erofeb deppots yeht sa gnidliub ytirohtuA tropsnarT eht fo rood tnorf eht ot gnitrad tpek ezag s'maiL .krow ot gnidaeh saw ehs taht derugif tevic eht dna
.senob nekorb rof kcehc ot
?thgirla worromot enin retfa llac t'nod tsuJ“
,tac eht rof ssenippah fo hsur a leef tub pleh t'ndluoc tevic ehT
,evivrus ot woh mih hcaet ot evah ew os
”...rre ,ruoy ot noitaredisnoc yna edam
tevic eht dlot gnihtemoS
,tfel eh erofeb thgir ssonS no ni dekeep dah eH
.edis eht pu bmilc ot esu eh epor a htiw metsys yellup a pu tes dah tuaseL tub
,srednuorG eht morf mih edih ot od nac sruecarT sa ew hcum os ylno s'erehT
,emit tsrif eht rof toN
,teparap eht deppirg ylthgil yeht sa
.nur dluoc yeht nehw evird ot esoohc dluow enoyna yhw derednow ssonS ...retal sraey owT
.sfoor eht no saw eh sa dnuorg eht no esae ta yltcefrep
.noitamriffa ni delbmum tuaseL
.elbuort diova ot spoc eht dediova uoy
yhcilC ni kcab rehtorb sih ot deneppah tahW
.ruf kciht sih etipsed
.erats tub pleh t'ndluoc tuaseL dna
tac eht fo mrof ehtil eht ta nwod dekool dna teparap eht no pu tog
.rehtruf og ot sgniw sih daerps eh sa mih tcetorp ot tub
”.ni emoc uoy erehw s'tahT
.ycavirp emos fo derussa saw eh os dekcoldap saw msinahcem hcniw ehT
.yawhtap ruoy fo trap era selcatsbo taht gnizilaer si
.tnemtrapa lautca na fo strofmoc eht lla mih evig ot selbac fo elpuoc a tcennoc ot elba saw ssonS ,kcolb eciffo na ot esolc sihT
tuaseL  .tuaseL dluow os dna
?txen sneppah tahW
.sessam eht fo retummoc a ,saw eh ereh tub
,nwonk reve dah eh gnihtyreve dniheb tfel eH
,evivrus ot woh denrael evah dluow ssonS
tuaseL .yllooc deksa maiL
,stnemelpmi latem gniltsihw eht degdod ylworran eh
”?lanimirc a ssonS sI
”.maiL ekil ysae ti ekat ot em sllet wolF eht llit syug uoy htiw nur llits ll'I tuB
,sneppah taht ecno dnA .sfoor eht ot ekat noos lliw yeht snaem taht ,mih retfa era spoc eht fI
,desu gnieb erew eW“
,sfoor eht ot koot spoc eht nehw yad a emoc dluow yehT
,boj rieht gniod ylpmis erew yehT
,denaorg eh dna ,detapissid saw llaf eht fo tnurb tsegral eht sa neve truh dna dehca ydob siH
.llaf ot detrats sraet dna
,71 kcolG sih werd tnaegres eht ,lrans suomonev a htiW
.liat dna ruf fo elbmuj a ni revo delbmut eh sa tlep sih fo strap lareves hctarcs prahs gnihtemos tlef eh dna
fo nwad eht saw tI .ytic eht ot lawener dna efil
,dellor eh dna yltcefrep epacse erif rewol a fo gnidnal etercnoc eht detcatnoc sfooh siH
,floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“:yojne esaelP
.mih ta kcab derats
.mih rof tiaw ot esroh eht gnillet eton a htiw stao deliob-emalf fo tsafkaerb a tfel dna
.noitautis eht ssessa ot kciuq saw tuaseL dna ,ssonS deirc ”!struh gel yM !kcuF“
.su hctac ot deirt ecilop nmad ehT“
,mrof lluf ni tac eht fo was eh tsal eht eb dluow siht
.enif m’I ,maiL ,yrrow t’noD .siraP ni kcab rehcaet taerg a yltcaxe t'nsaw I .lla s'taht ,ti tuoba suovren saw I“ .htaerb a ekat ot gnithgif ,dewollaws tuaseL ”...I“ ”?erofeb neppah siht ekil gnihtemos diD ?yltcaxe yhW
;thgirla eb ll'uoY“
.redluohs sih gnihctulc wap reh
.gnihctiwt ylerab srae ,mih sdrawot elzzum sih denrut maiL .deneppah tahw draeh eh sa noos sa nwod emoc dah dna
,pihsrotnem fo snier eht no gnissap nehw erafnaf dna ynomerec on saw erehT
tuaseL tub ,ekatsim tsetaerg sih neeb sah
,epyt yratilim suovren eht ekil dekool tem eh tcatnoc ehT
3 fo 3 trap
,tuaseL tem dah eh yad eht morf sredro tuo gnikrab netram enip eht dezingocer eH
,esrun a fo lerappa etihw-ffo eht ni desserd saw ehS
,no devom dah maiL
,esroh eht demialcxe ”!orb ,ni em tnuoC“
.detser won ssonS hcihw ni tnet
.feiler sih dih tevic ehT
.ne//:sptth egap ytiniffaruF ro rufikiW sih no
.egac gnivom a naht erom elttil saw elcihev a dna
)moc.yellavtibbar.www//:sptth( sserP yellaV tibbaR yb 0D3%egap62%52D3%rebmun_nruter62%hsarTB2%yrruFD3%txet_hcraesF3%php.hcraesF2%moc.yellavtibbar.wwwF2%F2%A3%sptth=lru_nruter&9089=meti?php.meti/moc.yellavtibbar.www//:sptth  .sserP yellaV tibbaR yb hsarT yrruF dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dessap setunim eht sa remlac werg maiL
,semitemos tub ,mih lortnoc tsap eht tel ot ton devloser dah eH
:elpmis erew sgniht ,yhcilC nI
.citpesitna dna sretsalp emos htiw pu rotnem dna
.eceiprae htooteulB sih hguorht llec eht dehctap eH
.flesmih rof yas dluoc tuaseL naht erom saw hcihw
,shtap sseltnuoc sti htiW
ffur kcen sih tsniaga trofmoc a won saw dna ,seiromem dab dleh regnol on tekcol s'rehtorb siH
,)ne=gnal?flowisakim/moc.rettiwt//:sptth(  floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“
.noinapmoc sih ot gninrut erofeb htaerb tsal eno koot maiL .”ma01-9
,efil s’arogna eht saw tnemevoM ehT
,eb dluow noitisop sih ni enoyna tub ,yadot yppah-reggirt saw netram ehT
.sredluohs sih ssorca mih gnipard
shtap deklaw eh taht ylnO
,setaf tnereffid dah meht fo llA
.tevic eht fo tuo erom gnihtyna teg ot gniog
gel s'esroh eht revo sdap sih gnisserp ,tuaseL dias
ecilop eht yb thguac neeb tsomla gnivah fo srettij eht naht rehtO
,hcneb a otno flesreh delttes dneirflrig s'maiL sa neve teef sih ot tog
.tnaegres a llits saw eh taht htrim emos htiw deton dna
.tuo dehtaerb eh sa tevic eht dias ”.esruoc fO“
,detiaw dna dneirf elyograg sih tsniaga ylbatrofmoc erom flesmih delttes
.sesseccus elttil s’efil fo noitamriffa na yad wen hcae
tnemevoM ehT pu nevig dah maiL
.dehtaerb eh sa sevooh sih gnihctulc
.mra sih no stops eht ta detniop
,ti fo gnivresed ssel on neeb dah
,sessam eht gnoma tsol eb dluow sruecarT eht dna
.ssonS deksa ”?ega fo gnimoC“
.tnemevoM ehT tfel yllaer dah maiL yhw wenk tuaseL neht saw ti dna
,gnoleb dna ,evivrus
.ot mih deredro dah niatpac sih smub eht pu dnuor ot gniliaf dna gniyrt
”.uoy htiw kcehc d'I taht mih dlot I
.mih htiw yadhtrib tsrif ’stik sih etarbelec ot ekil dluow ew fi deksa maiL
!gnidaer rof sknahT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.pleh ot snaem eht evah ew esle enoyna ro ssonS ot neppah ton tsum
,rehtona ot ti fo egats eno morf evom ot efil fo selcatsbo eht detnuomrus dah eh
.tas eh erehw tac eht hsarht ot deraperp saw eh ydaerla dna
,pu tog dna delrans
llaf rehtorb sih tel ohw eh saw tub
,kcen sih dnuora tekcol eht htiw delddif
tuaseL dna ,smaeb-I fo kcats a ot txen edis sih no yal ssonS
.yrekcirt on ,seil oN
detcepser dna wenk yeht taht srehto tub ,sevlesmeht tsuj ton sekat ti ,semitemoS
,floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“
,srehto ynam os fo naeco na ni tevic elttil eno
ti htiw gnignirb thgil fo syar
,dah leciC sa ksir yrassecennu na nekat dah ssonS
.nwod ruf sih peek ot thgif ot dah tuaseL dna
.ti morf denrael dah
.etaf fo ekorts a ni
.egarag yrots-itlum railimaf-oot-lla eht ni flesmih gnidnif
.kroY weN ekil tsuj buh tisnart yticretni na s'noitcesretnI“
?uoy sdnatsrednu ydobon erehw ecalp a ni ,lliw ruoy tsniaga dleh eb ot ekil s’ti tahw wonk uoY
,mih tcirtser ot ton
.decap eh sa
.tuoba gniyl yrenihcam dna sloot
,doohrobhgien a sdrawot gnihsad
tsap eht ni evil oT
?su tuoba amard lausu eht morf edisA“ .delkcuhc
,ylluferac dna ylwolS
.gnola semoc yug siht nehw ,ssenisub desrucca nwo ruo gnidnim ,era ew ereH .siht fo dnuos eht ekil t'nod I tuB !ton esruoc fO“
.meht ot evitcepsrep wen thguorb tser sa
,dereetnulov dah tnua siH
.egde s’foor eht sdrawot hsad eht edam dna
”?taht dnatsrednu uoy oD
,elddim eht nwod tilps egral a dah fooh thgir sih fo llaw ehT
,etal oot dnoces-retrauq a llor a ot deppord eH
latipsoh eht ni reh gniteem
.revo eetnem sih deppilf eh
,hgih pu morf neve elbidua erew maj ciffart gninrom-ylrae s'noitcesretnI fo sdnuos ehT
.dnuorg eht no sevil ruo dnif ot gnivah ,esoprup tuohtiw eb lliw ew dna
.noitats niart nwo yrev ruo ta smac yttihs eht morf esoht htiw noitats rieht ta egami sih decnerefer-ssorc evah tsum yehT
.mih revo tneb eh sa tuaseL deksa ”?ssonS ,yako uoY“
.teparap eht no detser swoble sih sa daeh sih gnuh
,uoy esimorp I tuB .neppah ot tihs siht fo yna tcepxe t'ndid I taht timda I ,tuaseL ,kooL“ .dehgis maiL
”,sseug I ,drah eid stibah dlO“ ”.taht
.tcelgen yb yawa nrow yhposolihp dna sfeileb tnatropmi
.mih steg reven ehs erus ekam ll'I ,evila m'I sa gnol sa dna
,riahtrohs hsitirB elamef a saw mih ediseB
,ecalphtrib sih morf selim eb yam eH
?ssonS ,gnikniht uoy erew tahW“
.rethgiarts pu gnitaes
.mih sdrawot delbmuts
.rebmun eht was eh nehw dennirg ecaf s'esroh eht dna ,gnar llec siH
.gnarps dna nav a tsniaga pu nar ssonS dna
,sgnithgis latigid dna
.maerd gnissap a tsuj s’ti won tub
,ecalp txen eht ot ylerem ton
.meht ni ecalp fo tuo dna elbatrofmocnu rehtar gnikool ,sehtolc krow eciffo ni saw eh ereh dna
gniht emas ehT .mih deveileb
tuaseL ,saw esroh eht naht rethgil hcum os gnieb etipseD
,gnidliub detelpmocnu na fo pot no saw eh taht was tevic eht
nruter sih rof gnidnamed s’ehs yhw nosaer eht dna
.edir a gnihctac revo loohcs ot gniklaw esohc eh nehw desirprus fo trohs gnihton neeb dah sreep siH
,evil ot erised A
,kcab sih no stuc eht desuac evah dluoc taht sirbed fo dne on saw ereht ,nwod gnikooL
tuaseL ”.laveirter sih rof eciton a tuo tup tnua siH .su fo tser eht ekil tsuj ,yawanur a s'eH
,mih rof derac reven tnua siH
.ssonS gnirotnem tuoba deirrow demees uoy ,yadot reilraE
,tluav hsad a ni arromaC a revo delias
.tes VT sih no denrut eh sa
,saw eh ruecarT eht ekiL
.etuc ytterp er'yehT
ytic eht gniwonk htiw emac taht ylrailimaf ehT
,ruf sih otni dekaos dniw eht sa neve
denimreted saw esroh eht
?fo egrahc ni s'eh seludehcs sub dna niart ynam woh wonk uoy oD
.tuaseL denaorg ”?thguat I gnihtyreve nettogrof uoy evaH
,sub a morf gnithgila tlep etalocohc s’arogna eht fo mrof tcnitsid eht dettops
?mih nopu tsurht ytud eht fo yhtrow
,thgirpu ylwols dereggats eh sa dnuora kool a gnikaT
.tnemevoM ehT ro efil ni ti eb
.ot rewsna ot ssob liat-eht-ni-niap
.ledom elbatrop a yub ot hguone mih denrae tuaseL edisgnola enod dah eh sboj fo elpuoc a tub
.eno trohs a ylno saw
,gnab a htiw nepo rood ycnegreme eht deredluohs eh sa neve ylthgils debbur
,denrecnoc yleniuneg saw eh taht ees dluoc tuaseL ,ffo pac sih htiW .maiL deksa
.cra gninnips a otni drawrof mih gniworht sgel gnigniws sih fo mutnemom eht
!tnemevoM ehT ot sthgir rieht esol lliw nerhterb ruecarT ruo fo lla
.devil eh sa gnol sa ti peek ot denimreted saw eh dna
!gnola teg sgod dna stac woh tsuj wonk uoy dnA
detnuh a ekil thgin elohw eht redluohs sih revo gnikool saw ssonS dnA“ .tuaseL dednamed
.efil sih ecnahc wen a
tuaseL  .emac yeht sa sgniht ekat ot wenk tnemevoM ehT fo esoht rof
.koorc on t’nia ssonS
,su pleh ot ti gniod saw eh taht
,mih sdrawot detrats dah spoc eht ydaerlA
,flesmih truh dah eh nehw ecnahc yb evol sih dnuof dah eH
?niaga deneppah ti fi tahW
,mlac fo ksam a saw ecaf siH .maiL dias
.detaucave eb ot mlac esroh eht dedeen tuaseL dna
.ti dnuora sgnidliub eht yb denetfos naht rehtar deifilpma
,snaej dna strihs-eet fo tnemtrossa sih naht rehto gnihtyna raew maiL nees reven dah eH
”?deen I od ecnedive erom tahW
,saw eh erehw morf yaw gnol a emoc dah eH
,epacse-raen sih retfa yltrohS
.edispot eht ni thgis fo tuo gniyats
”?nodnoL ni evah yeht uoy dlot I smac rekcart esoht rebmemeR“
.sfooh sih ot txen thgir gnirettalc nug eht
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoy dna
.noitailater morf efas hcum ytterp erew yeht ,spoc eht gnitruh dediova sruecarT eht sa gnol sA
.spoc eht rof yrros tsomla tlef eh
.kcab htnom a meht nees ev'I“
*** .efil sih fo egats txen eht tub
”.gnideelb s'tlep ruoy dnA
.elpicsid sih ot eybdoog tnelis a gniddib retsam a
.ysae ti sah maiL kniht uoy fi gnimoc gniht a tog ev'uoy dnA“
tuaseL ,ma05.8 sa emit eht dewohs kcolc cilbup eht sa tsuJ
.skrow wolF eht woh ton s'tahT“
,dehctertstuo smra htiw drawrof ydob sih gniworhT
.rafa morf neve elbisiv spih tnenimorp reh
,lennahc swen eht nO
mih rof gnitiaw eb dluow esle ohw dnA
.ti ot gnieerga tuoba tnatiseh saw ssonS dna
.derekcilf seye
,erom ecno retnec ytic eht raen tops siht ot enola yaw sih edam dah eH
.maiL ,em lleT“ *** .tnemevoM ehT
,pu tes tluciffid elttil a neeb dah gninoitidnoc-ria eht taht timda ot dah eH
a ylniatrec saw tahT ”?yhw tuB“
sfoor eht revo tuo gnirats
.etercnoc ytrid eht gniniats
.raef dna doolb fo tnecs eht morf gnihctiwt deppots reven eson s'etoyoc eht hguoht
t'nsaw eh tub ,decnivnoc kool t'ndid maiL .arogna eht ta kcab elims a decrof eH ”.esimorp I tahT .ssonS fo erac doog ekat ll'I .peels doog a retfa yako eb ll'I
.yltneitapmi deddon tuaseL sa maiL deksa
.noitcesretnI fo sfoor eht no yllagelli gnivil neeb dah smuldooh fo rebmun nwonknu na eveileb ot nosaer dah yeht taht decnuonna dah ecilop eht
.dednuoser hself no latem fo skcarc eht sa lley spoc eht draeh dna
,troppus fo ecruos ylno sih sA
,saw I loof eht gnieb ,I dna
tsuj naht erom ni lufesu eb ot nwohs dah selcsum denot sih tsael tA
.enola ti fo nedrub eht raeb ot dah eh dna
.trats eht morf ti detah dah dna ,neetxis denrut eh nehw snossel gnivird rof enog dah eH
,noitcesretnI ot emoc dah eh yhw wenk eno oN
,gnikconk emoc reve wal eht dluohS
,sgnithgis ssentiw demrifnocnu morf edisA
.elims a htiw tac eht dias ”,em hcaer ot woh wonk uoy ,lleW“
,cinap ot mih rof saw neppah dluoc taht gniht tsrow ehT
ria gninrom eht ot daeh sih detfil eH
.ot pu kool ot enoemos sdeen eH .enola si
,ned sih fo tuo deppets eH .ssonS dehgual
.tuaseL ,ekat ot mih rof hcum oot saw ti tub ,ytic eht htiw ytirailimaf sih ,ylimaf ,sdneirf
,wollof dluow taht syad eht ni taht gniwonk
,sdaor nepo emaceb syawyella dekcolB .dah esle eno on
,modeerf sih deyojne esroh eht tuB
.mih rof pu tes lla tnemevoM ehT ni nossel etelpmoc a saw ereh tub
,rehtruf og ot eno rof seitinutroppo wen emac segnahc htiw dnA
:tnatsissA scitsigoL rof weivretnI ni-klaW“
,dias dah nushA sa ,tsap eht ni gniyats ton ,drawrof gnivom tuoba saw efiL
tuaseL ”.yerg s’rehto eht elihw mih ekil nworb s’meht fo owT
.dnats retsop a no dracalp a gnittes ,tuo deppets flow demrofinu a dna
.emoh sih saw taht ytic eht fo esnepxe tsav eht ta nwod gnikool
,llup eht fo mutnemom eht ni thguaC.
.mih ediug ot tnemevoM ehT dna diuq derdnuh a naht ssel htiw ereh niart eht koot
.os eb ot evah t'ndid ti tub
tnemecalpsiD fo trA ehT ot yek ehT“
.ytinummoc eligarf rieht nihtiw drocsid dna gnidnatsrednusim diova ot srehto eht morf terces tpek eh enoemos
a htiw eesrevo ot sah eh setanidrobus fo rebmun eht noitnem ot toN
,pmuj rieht ni tsoob taht meht evig ot
”?edam tsuj uoy esimorp eht tcarter uoy lliw ,si eh fI“
demeed saw tahw no sretroper yb deliassa saw royam gnikool-delggah a
.mih dnif meht tel t'nac ew ,si ti revetahW
etipser rieht wenk tuaseL dna ,ffo raf morf emac sneris ecilop fo dnuos ehT
sedis sih gnihctulc
.ssergorp yna htiw pu emoc ot tey sah ecilop eht
.ssonS dehgien ”,rotneM ,oY“
.sdrow eht htiw gnola gnicnuob saw eh noos dna ,ycnaf sih koot gnos klof alagnil A
.neve detaluclac ,luferac saw eciov siH
.seitluciffid s'efil fo yna morf yawa nur ot ton
,ytinutroppo wen a elcatsbo hcae
ylikeehc esroh eht dias
,debbos eh sa delkcub seenk s’tuaseL ,dnuorg eht morf mih detarapes taht thgieh eht ta nwod gnikooL
,ekops elamef eht sa neve
”,nekorb s'taht fooh ruoy ylno s’ti
tuaseL ”.em rof yllaicepsE
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
taht dezilaer tuaseL ,kcab gnikooL
,nrut egral a nekat tsuj dah efil siH
,gniknilb tuohtiw saw eh erehw deyats maiL tuB
.tneserp eht ni eid ot saw
fo strap #3 fo #3 eht
”?eh t’nsi ,gnihtemos rof detnaw s’eh tuB
tuaseL .dereffo ti sdlohwap dna toof suoirav eht yb gnidliub eht nwod gniwolf wodahs tnelis a
.thgindim ylraen saw ti wonk ot ti ta kool ot deen t'ndid eh tub ,hctaw latigid dlo na dah
,suoicsnoc llits saw esroh eht ,feiler sih oT