,etevian s’tacbob eht ta dehgis newG ”,noH“
:niraeh ro niees a-daets
,thgindim retfa s’ti dna
.skcart eht no doots ilE
”?aedi tseb eht si enituor noitanalpxe tsohg elohw eht erus uoY“
,thgin eht fo tuo gnihtemos egavlas ot tpmetta tnerappa ni ,htuR
”.ma’am ,os yas uoy fI“ .dehgis htuR
”,epyt-bus a llac ahctahw s’rekihhctih lartceps A“
,derettalc gnihtemoS
”?enim eht me dewohs uoy nehw nevE“
.emit emos rof taht ekil tas yehT
.lacitpeks dednuos htuR
,nieb ecnereffiD
”,yawyna ,ereh swodniw nialp n’erom droffa ot elba neeb a-t’ndluow yehT“
.edisni morf ti tops ot elba eb t’ndluow yeht neht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.devom elttil a eb tub pleh t’ndluoc neB
”.knird a esu dluoc I tub ,tsirhC“
tub anavriN ti llac elpoep emoS
,sailE sa flesmih decudortni dah
”?rohcna na sa regna gnisu si tsiegretlop a oS“
…sseug I oS .lahcrairtap tib
.sllaw eht rof sporp otni meht nrut
,no nael ot hguone mrif ti degduj
.kcab ti teg ot elba eb ot erar ytterp s’ti ,sedisbus esle revetahw r’regna eht fI
.ot epoh reven t’nod I dna
”!srinevuos gnikat oN“
”!ssergorp s’taht lleW“
.enim eht no dexif seye sih tpek ilE ”.os ylerus ,hO“
,lanoitnetni tnia stsiegretlop tsom
,desserpmi dekool ilE
.rood a eb ot desu ereht erehw sseuG
.eno saw eh naem t’ndluow tahT
.esnes lacinhcet tsom eht ni sllaw rehto ylno erew erehT
”.stsixe llits teg ot niyrt er’yeht reverehw sa gnol ,lleh
”.ffun‘ noos nitnuah reporp eht teg ll’ew ,terf t’nod tuB
.ekil-etarebiled erom si me fo emos tuB
,pots ot stnaw eh ebyaM“ .denway newG
”.detsixe yllaiciffo nwot eht n’regnol elttil a yllacinhcet llits
,enim eht ot resolc og ot meht gnirad etiuq ton
.ruot eht gnivig yllautca fo daetsni
.nibac rieht dnuora efil ot ekow tresed hgih eht sa
,yrotagrup hguorht niog s’yeht yas sklof emoS
.doolb a’mrof eht ni yllausU
.daeh sih koohs ilE ”.od ylerus yehT“
”.t’nod tsiegretlop A .ssip a ekat ro
yaw eht ni si nihtyna fi dna
.no niog s’tahw llet naC
.ylkrad ,dias newG
”-htiw kcab nimoc morf tsohg emas eht nippots nihton t’nia tuB
”?doog eb ytinrete“
.mottob eht dehcaer tsim tub gnihton taht hguone niht dna hgih
,dessih htuR ”,tiaW“
,esle gnihtemos otni detfihs kool desserpmi eht dna
dah taht sllaw ysmilf eht tsniaga dnas nwolbdniw fo elahxe esraoh a saw dnuos ylno ehT
”,a saw eh fi ,ekiL
.hcti kcen sih fo kcab eht pu selacs eht gnikam saw taht drayevarg a eb ot ti wenk eh taht tcaf eht tsuj saw tI
.goD fo ecioV eht no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,foor lepahc despalloc eht fo niur eht deppetsedis dah htuR ”,yaS“
,yaw emas eht ,noitca emas eht staeper
.etisnwot eht no stops evitca tsom eht a eno eb atesu sihT"
.pots hcaocegats a neeb ecno
.yttiw os ti dnif ot mees t’ndid—
.stneduts ynam evah ot noitalupop hguone reven saw ereht hguoht
”.ma’am ,ereh tsohg a si ylerus ereht hO“
,reh ot denrut ilE
,seirots tsohg ni fitom detaepeR
”?ereh nees neeb evah“
”?yrgna siht deid yeht taht
.nivil eht morf nelots efil naht rohcna retteb a sekam nihton :elpmaxe roF“
”.wollof I erus ton m’I“
,deggurhs ilE ”.yawyna ,tey toN
,rohcna on tnaw t’nod ohw tsohg a pu niggard ,emahs nmaD“
”?nitatidem yna enod reve uoy
.edistuo morf ni detfird eciov s’ilE ”.tirips lanrete na erup a s’tahw tsohg a htiw enon tcaretni yllaer t’nac nivil eht woh noitnem ot toN“
”.ekil eht dna sesno-yas nikcuF
.ssyba s’enim eht otni derats neB
”?taht seod tsohg fo dnik tahw dnA“ ".evila
ekil sgniht s’ereht erehw esrevinu eht a-reyal eht htiw hcuot ni peek ot no nisucof s’tsohg a revetahw sej s’rohcna nA“
,delims newG .pu depip htuR
naht retteb od t’ndluoc tub
”.derohcna yats ot erom nilaets peek tog uoY
.tsulrednaW fo floW ,neguuY yb daeR
seigolohtna rehto dna
,sretfar eseht evom ot dah evah dluow enoemoS
,ytinrete ni s’ti
,neeuQ rednuhT eht
.sroodni og ot denrut sivaD dna ilE
.pots hcaocegats eht“
.rohcna eht si flesti noitacol eht nehw si
”.yaw ruo no teg tseB
thgilyad gnisir ehT
pukcip dlo detsur eht ni devirra d’ohw tibbarkcaj ehT
,htob meht derongi newG
?ecalp siht tuoba su llet uoy dluoc“
.flesmih deveileb yltrap ylno eH
”,owt r’gniht a denrael ev’I ,hO“
.ksat sih ot flesmih derehtager dah ediug rieht
,nethgil ot nugeb dah noziroh nretsae eht mih dniheB
”?suoregnad erom era taht“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sllih tnadrev ylihctap eht denekawa dna detanimulli
a yb deliassa saw eh
”?esoprup no stsohg gniyats era“
..tsulrednaW fo floW
”?neht ,htiarw a ees ot ton
”.taorht sih morf tsehc sih nwod niruop doolb ees ’nnog uoy ,yas yeht
”,stsohg tuoba dnatsrednu ot tog uoy gniht tsrif ehT“
”.esops I ,ffun riaF“
,selttob elpuoc a sekat ehS
.raey txen niaga yrt ll’uoy tcepxe I ,lleW“
”.ma’am tsiegretlop a s’tahT“
”.debrutsid nieb atuo tsuj
.tsal t’nod ti tpecxE
,renroc eht dnuora tperc neB ”?ot naeM“
,tey hcruhc on evah t’ndid nwot moob ninim a llet draeh yranoissim emos
,reverof gniht emas eht seod tsuj taht tsohg a uoy steg yromem a
.reppoc dedorroc fo roloc eht ni nwad eslaf yb deniltuo sasem dehtoot-pag dna sniatnuom deggaj
,teknalb a ekil mih no gnihgiew saw thgin eht fo sseniraew ehT
”,raey yreve ero ssel n’ssel tog yeht yas yehT“
.reverof tsal ll’luos eht ,eruS“
”.sraey rof ,nikrow ot esolc emoc s’esle nihtoN
.ruot eht no tops txen eht ot meht dael ot denrut ilE
.gnol detsal me fo enon ,seman wef a dah ecalP“
.dnif ot sthgilhsalf eht rof gnihton saw ereht
,ti dnatsrennu I s’raf oS“
,dekrow stsohg woh gninialpxe tuoba tnetsisni yllufwa saw eH“
.enog saw gnidliub eht fo foor ehT ”.odnanreH ydoolB
”.seye sih revo nwod dellup tah
,lleps ro tcatnoc cihcysp ro esruc adnik emos s’rohcna eht nehw’S
nihc reh rednu pu enihs ot denoitisop ylsuoicsnocnu
,kcen sih fo kcab eht ta selacs htooms eht debbur neB ”,t’ndluohS“
.klahc ro skoob nworht"
”?raeh’y ,won ,efas levart lla uoY .nokcer I
.esuohloohcs eht ni erehwemos
”.no nivom trats dna rohcna rieht a og tel
”.tnemniatretne s’gnineve gnitnioppasid a tsuj saw ti ebyam rO“
,on ”,a erew ereht fI“
?snruter relevart on ecnehw morf yrtnuoc derevocsidnu eht
,sehcra wodniw ytpme eht rednu thgilhsalf reh gniyalp saw
efil rieht morf wenk yeht nihtemos ot dehcatta si stnuah tsom teb d’I dnA
”.nidne on tog t’nia wonk yeht ksat emos atno dloh llew yrev thgim yeht tub
,esor yllanif nus eht nehW
,98 yawhgih no
.mih ot denrut rennurdaor dna tacbob eht nehT
.noos eb annog s’esirnus ,lleW“
,nialpxe ot deraperp eh ,stsohg fo esuaceb toN
,eulb leets neht ,wolley neht
.resolc on worg sesseug eht llits dna ecno naht erom eulc yreve deirt s’ohw reyalp sedarahc a ekil
,gnidliub fo ksuh wolloh siht ot resolc gnipeerc erew ,gnihtyna ro
.levarg toofrednu fo hcnurc eht rednu ,derepsihw newG
.rood tnorf eht edistuo deniamer ilE
,ediw erew seye s’tibbarkcaj ehT
,detcepxe eb dluoc sa elbats sa ti degduj
”.skrow ti dlot neeb I woh ninialpxe sej m’I
.ytisoiruc rey yfsitas ot sej
.puorg eht morf yawa decaf ilE
,sevlesmeht ot niod er’yeht tahw dna era yeht tahw sezilaer ylluf dna yllaer tsohg yna ro
.emoceb dah nwot eht denodnaba woh no gnidneped evoba eht fo noitanibmoc emos ro
?I t’nevah ,esle nihtyreve deirt I“
.yks fo ecnelis sselmottob a dna ,tresed sselhtap
.rehtona ro rohcna adnik eno gnisu t’nia sa seno eht tcatnoc ot elba eb t’ndluow ew
.dehcterts dna teef sih ot tog knuks eht ”?og ti d’woH“ .rood rac a neeb dah dnuos eht dnA
.sraeppasid neht dna
,meht derussa ilE
,stnanever ro stnuah sa
”.taht ref nosaer a s’ereht tuB“ ,dias ilE
.dnuora ssem na ereh pu evird ot desu sdik“
I semit elpuoC“
.diasnu deniamer ’esuohloohcs a ni yllaicepse‘ esarhp ehT
.flesym ,taht n’erom hay llet t’ndluoC
,ssenisub dehsinifnu erom on tog s'tnanever a ro
,gnihtyreve saw ereht meht dnuorA
”?esuoh detnuah a teg uoy woh s’taht dnA“
teb d’I“ .ylkrad dias ilE
”?stsohg era seripmav gniyas uoy era“
.detsixe llits dlrow eht fo gnihtyna rehtehw erus eb t’ndluoc neB hcihw fo sllaw eht dnoyeb
yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb ”sgnitnuaH ni nosseL A“ saw sihT
.gnitsisni saw htuR
:niga og tib eht s’woH“
”…nataS pu gnirb ot tuoba er’uoy fI“
,pucrettub tresed dna deewerif fo llems eht
”.dniheb raf t’nerew nwot eht neht dna ,nwod tuhs ecalp eht llit“ ,dedulcnoc ilE
,hguone gnorts s’ti f’noitome yna eb naC“
,71 etuor no tsew ro
:noitalosi s’emoh rieht etipsed
,no ssap annaw t’nod taht seno eht dnA
…ekil’S ’.emit‘ na ’ecalp‘
.tfil a hctih ot gniyrt
,redrah tol a sucof nac uoy tuo snrut
.sdnaS rettiB ot mih ekat ot—
,emarfrood lepahc eht detset ylsuoituac ilE
,dog knaht ,flesym eno no pu nur reven
”,neht ,stsohg fo dnik tahW“
!erad uoy fi ,eracs doog
.efas t’nerew sa sgniht otni teg d’yeht tub
.rehtohcae ta dekool newG dna htuR
.tneloiv teg ll’sa stsohg a’stros ylno eht a’eno s’yeht a tnuocca no tsuj ton dna
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf
”,ereht ni deid ev’elpoep“ tuB
,sraey ytnewt n’ssel nepo saw ti lla ni llA
.yaw taht no tpek dna yrgna deid tsuj yeht
”?efil s’ydobemos eb at’esu tahw fo sparcs eht ni dnuora nissem eracs nuf doog a flesrey evah annaw uoy ekil rO ?si tsohg a tahw dnatsrednu annaw uoy
.rohcna na flesrey deen uoy
tibbarkcaj ehT .fo kniht dluoc ehs sgnitnuah dna srohcna tuoba snoitseuq eht lla gniksa saw dna ssennrobbuts s’ediug eht ot ni thguob ylluf dah
.eciton ll’nivil ydobyna sgniht od tsohg a ekam ll’taht eno eht s’regna yltsom tsuj
,ereht ni tsohg fo dnik taht-
,egnahc a fo hcum ekam t’ndluow taht kramer ot detpmet saw neB ”.edisni niog ton
,ytrap a ot neeb s’ehs ekil desserd namow gnuoy a netfo s’ti ,ees s’teL
dnim s’neB otni dehsalf thguoht A ”.tnanever a fo“
,elpoep ,serutcip ,sllod ,sesuoh tsuj tnia ti dna—
?neeb drow eht dah tahw
,htap eht fo edis eno ot deppets eH .dias eh lla saw
”.rehtien taht rof tliub yllaer tnia dnim latrom
”,ereht llits s’yehT“ ”?ereht llits s’yehT“
.desirprus yllufthguoht dekool tibbarkcaj eht
.emas eht hcum yrev kool meht edam dah htaed
meht tahw si sihT“
”,sessag yvaeh …ekil s’ereht dnA“
”’,strepxe lamronarap‘
,esormirP ninevE ehT
ereh teg ot rehto eht r’yaw eno ti nekat ev’atfah adluow lla’y—
.sdnaS rettiB fo nwot gninim
,daor eht fo edis eht no mih ees ll’uoy semitemos neht
.yrellag yrruFoS sih ta ro
,snignoleb rieht ,esuoh rieht—
,ilE ediseb taes sih deniager sivaD
”,ruot siht nivig detrats I erofA“ .yleruS
”.noitairporppa larutluc s’ereht taht
.noitartsurf htiw dessih ilE ”.ti leef dluoc I
.dnuora kcits ot dnet t’nod tsiegretlop a“ ,dettimda ilE
,pots tsal eht tih ew erofA“
.deksa neB ”?erehw oT“
,yas ot tnegilletni gnihtemos fo kniht ot tseb sih did neB
”.tser emos deen htob ew ,nom’C
.eerga ot dah kniks ehT
,pu mih kcip ot pots uoy fi nihton yas t’now eH“
,senip burcs eht hguorht ezeerb looc fo dnuos eht
,deunitnoc ilE ,ecnelis fo stnemom wef a retfA
,yaw taht dnuora sklaw
”.ydaerla tnia ew fi ereh nihton ees ot ylekil tniA
.elbasu nehw neve tcapmoc dna tauqs neeb evah dluow gnidliub ehT ".denodnaba
,noynac xob eht fo dne eht ni eloh krad eht drawot deddon ilE
”?retsim ,si tsohg a tahw tuoba su llet uoy nac tahw“ ,pu ekops neht
.taht ekil nihtmuS
,hcuot latnemirepxe na gnidliub eht fo renroc eht evag ilE ",nignab duoL"
.rood esuohloohcs gnitsil eht ffo seye sih gnikat tuohtiw derewsna ilE
.aera gnikrap eht ot gnissorc daorliar eht morf klaw trohs a saw tI
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,stsiegretlop ,ssenisub daB“
”,yas ot tluciffiD“ .deksa newG
.rewsna na dah htuR ron neB rehtieN
.detartsurf dna delffab
?taht od ot sruot eseht no gnimoc pots ot elpoep sdeen eh tub“
.lliw fo ecrof reehs yb mrif eciov sih tpek kniks eht
dias dna delims ilE giws a retfA
,flesti yb luos A“
.ecnartne eht ot kcab sih denrut ilE
”,deniatniamnu dna ,krad s’tI
tnemom gnol a retfa tuB
,egnever nitteg s’taht ebyam
.gniretne tsniaga dediced neB
.dias htuR ”?tahW“ ”.thgin ta
.odnanreH neeb evah t’ndluow ti dnA
.sdnaS rettiB fo nwot eht neeb ecno dah tahw fo tsud eht tub gnihton detanimulli wap sih ni thgilhsalf ehT
”.tsiegretlop atros tnreffid a ebbem s’taht os
”?wohemos mih dneffo I diD“
gnitsujda erew seye sih taht ecalp sselthgil siht ni hguone gnol tneps d’yeht yltnerappa tub
”,ti raeh’t dooG“ ”.uoy evol od I“
.tnuocsid laiceps rof elbigile stnedutS
,regaw d’I ,siht dnA
”,cificeps ,ereh hcum nees t’nia I“
”?rohcna sih si nwot eht fo sruot tsohg gnivig ebyam dna ,tnanever a“
”?tuoba gniklat uoy era tahW“ ”.dniw ehT“
,ees’y ,luos daed A
tae ro peels attog uoy yllautneve
,dias neB ”,esle ohW“
.seirots tsohg tub gnihtyna rof ecneitapmi reh lla dednepxe dah htuR
,lacitpeks dednuos newG
,elpeets dehsawetihw a neeb ecno dah tahw fo egakcerw eht no pu gel eno denael ilE
.dehcaorppa nwad eht sa ,flesti tressa ot gninnigeb saw sseniraeW
.wodniw a hguorht nworht liap hcnul a ro nispalloc flehs a emoc syawla dluow retfa dna
”,tsohg adnik eno si erehT“
,drawrof meht devaw ilE
.keehc eht no ssik lufetarg a reh evag
”?ruoT nwoT tsohG thgindiM dellac gnihtemos rof pu sngis“
,lanoitacude yrev eb lliw ecneirepxe eht tbuod t’nod ew dna ,yllaicepse
.ssenkrad eht otni sklaw dna rac eht atuo steg eh ,t’nod uoy fI
,ees’y ,esuohloohcs eht saw sihT
,hguorht thgir klaw ll’ti
”?ereh tsohg a s’ereht rehtehw dnA
,retne ot gnilliw yltnerappa saw eh gnidliub a ot meht thguorb yllanif dah ilE ”,eb ot desu sihT“
erehw dedworc moorb hctocs dna ,deewelbmut ,eltsihT
”,ees’y ,noitome na s’rohcna eht nehw sneppah tahw’S“
,hguoht ,ksa ot egaruoc eht nommus dluoc neB erofeB
.sredluohs sih dnuora mra na tup
…oot ro das oot ro deracs oot
dias ylno eh tuB
”.lla si emahs a s’tI“ ”.wonk I“ ”...enim denmednoc a otni derednaw sa sdik emos seJ“ ”.wonk I“ ”.lla si ,me rof yrros leef seJ“
,nekcihc a mih dellac
.daetsni ’gnidnecsnart‘ yas emos
”,no evom nac eh os
,emit tsrif eht roF
,taht sparcs eht lla dna
,dewollaws eh ”,taht seod tI“
.ssenkrad elbartenepmi erom neve na otni
.edis rehto eht oT“
,ereh pu llup uoy emit eht yb neht …od uoy fi tuB
.yrutnec a revo rof neeb dah ti sa ytpme sa sdnaS rettiB neeb ecno dah taht nwot eht dnuof ti
.suoregnad eb d’ti ,naem I“
”.me ot derrucco sa gniht tsrif eht saw taht
.yletinifedni no yrrac tsuj nac taht neht
.edisni og dluohs enoyna ecalp a ekil kool t’ndid sihT
”.daed er’yeht wonk t’nod taht stsohg nialpxe t’ndluoc uoy esiwrehto“ ,desum newG
gnitnuah A .eciton reven
”.gniod saw eh tnecca taht ekiL .pihsnamwohs
,eno ta dellik saw ehs gniylpmi
,nihc sih rednu selacs eulb eht dehctarcs eh ”…ebyam oS
.drayevarg llams eht fo egde eht ta ,tnemehev erom
rennurdaor eht dna tacbob ehT
,meht fo hcae revo kool a tpews eH
,lehtorb eht ,gnilbmag eht ,noolas eht rof derehtag evah dluow srenim eht ecno
”?neht ,meht ta retteb eb eh t’ndluohS“
.scisyhpatem deilppa tuoba etaluceps ot esucxe eht nekat tsuj evah thgim ohw ,floWcaM boR yb
,efil morf noitome na ot no dloh ot eganam nac tsohg a fI“
”.tsohg eht ot niod si dlrow gnivil eht ni nihtemos taht nihtyna
,neguuY yb daeR
taht tsuj saw ti flesmih llet ot deirt neB
etats erup sti nI
,enoyna fi taht neddibnu
,rorrim weivraer eht ni mih ta kool uoy fi tuB
,yawrood eht no maeb thgilhsalf sih dexif tibbarkcaj ehT .ezorf lla yehT
,mih derad seillub drayloohcs neesnu
.t’nthguo yeht sgniht htiw sseM
,rac eht ni enola er’uoy dna
.rohcna adnik rehtona htiw kcab gnimoc morf-“
”,regna ylirassecen ton ,lleW“
,rettib dna ruos enog dah eciov s’tibbarkcaj eht
.ko si nik rieht erus nikam ro
.mih ot devaw yeht ”,erac ekaT“
”.sa pu niwohs er’uoy tsohg adnik tahw snaem
.devirra d’yeht nehw dnuora nevird d’yeht taht sllihtoof eht otni tuo dnuow
.spets hcrop eht pu teef derit sih deggard eh sa dehgis ilE
.ereht teg yeht erofa hsinav tsuj nac yeht neht
,no niog s’tahw llet dna kniht ot rohcna on deen t’ndid yeht fi neve oS“
.yks eht ni sulumuc detarutas-nus fo sniatnuom sselpot eht dna
,detsuahxe tsuj saw dnim sih taht nwot denodnaba siht ni gnol os tneps d’eh esuaceb ylbissop
.tiplup eht neeb evah dluow tahw ta gnidnats flesmih dnuof neB
.srohcna rieht lla fo og tel tsohg a fi neppah dluow tahw deksa d’ehs litnu selballysonom lattimmocnon ni derewsna dah
llafretaw a ekil—
”,otni denrut ero a’tnuoma laer yna dah sa eno ylno ehT
,tsehc reh ot thgilhsalf reh dellup dah htuR
”,skaeps eh emit ylnO“ .desoppus neB
”.gniht lufraef a s’taht dna
,emit ni t’nia tirips a dnA
,knip nrut yks eht dehctaw yehT
,nworgrevo dna denodnaba saw daorliar ehT
,tniop siht ta tser emos detnaw tsuj yllaer neB
,me ot deneppah tahw
”.ti tuoba kniht ,lleW“
,ereh morf ,daor ssecca ehT
”,taht ekil ti tup uoy nehw ,lleW“
”?neht ,ni og ot efas eb t’ndluow ti
,detcepxe dah neB naht regnol neeb dah etis enim dlo eht ot pu klaw ehT ”.siht“
”.erom on ereht t’nia eh
,niaga nivil eht elbuort nac uoy taht nihtemos a-hguone eb ot redro nI
’.ssenisub dehsinifnu‘ tuob no og yeht nehw tuoba niklat yllautca si“ ,deffocs ilE
”,srohcna deen stsohg dias uoY“
.haey ,taht ekil nihtemoS“ ”?artnam a ro“
.ecnatsid htiw gnidaf
’eripmav‘ yas t’ndluoc eh ,thguoht neB
,ytisoiruc rieht me egdurgeb t’nod I ,hO
.htiarw a llac ahctahw s’taht dna
.noziroh deilpmi eht dnoyeb ti wollof ot detnaw llits eye eht tub
.nihtiw gnihton detanimulli tub
.dehsinif nihtemos teg ot denimreted si sa seno s’ereht nehT .tnuoc d’esohT ?deid yeht nehw ta nikrow erew yeht saw ti revetahw ,lleh
”.raey tsal n’retteb oN“
.ylevarg daeh sih koohs tibbarkcaj ehT
”,tsohg fo dnik tahW .oS“
,ssenkrad eht otni gnireep htiw detneirosid saw eh esuaceb spahrep
”.llits ,lla n’dnuorg detarcesnoc sa stnuoc ebbeM .ereh detroper neeb s’nithgis oN ?ereH“
”?ereh dnif uoy od“
.tsenrae yldaed ni dednuos ediug eht tub
”.leehw sirref a nidir er’uoy elihw dnuorg eht no nidnats allef a htiw klat a evah ot niyrt ekil eb dluoW
…ekiL ?woh detseretnI“
.ni gniog ton rof
,ilE ot denrut eh nehW
hsurbegas eht ni sadacic dna gnosdrib eht ot denetsil dna
,ecalp emos nitteg si ot no nignah er’yeht gniht eht fI
’.tsohg a‘ tsuj sa elpmis sa t’nia ti si“
’,yam-yats-ipe tcerid‘ llac d’uoy tahw yb swonk tsuj
.depmuj neB dna dekaeuqs newG ”!hO“
,deunitnoc ilE ”,yas yehT“
”.emit siht ,ni og t’ndid yehT“
,wol sworb ,ediw seye
.smirgliP me llac sklof emoS“
.lairetam eht ton dna dlrow tirips eht tsuj nitibahni rof tliub t’nia dnim latrom eht tuB
,nihtyna nrael ro egnahc t’nac
.erew esoht tahw wonk t’ndid eh ekil gnidnuos tuohtiw erew esoht tahw ksa ot yaw a fo kniht ot deirt neB
.erew esoht tahw wonk ydaerla ot desoppus saw eh ekil mih ta dekool ilE
.rehtie htap rieht gnikcolb yltcaxe ton tub
.selop eht pu nittup hsinif dluoc yeht erofa deid nwot eht tub oot eciffo hpargelet a eb ot tnaem saW
,yliranidro ,eviecrep ot tniaf oot neeb evah dluow—thgilnoom emac
,luftcepsersid repus t’nerew ti fi neve“
.gnivird deirt eh erofeb rac sih ni pan tsuj ot thguo eh ebyam
.elbatrofmocnu dekool htuR dna newG
,hguone tnetsisnoc na ,hguone evitca s’taht ereh dnuor stsohg ylno eht a’eno rof rohcna eht dnif ll’uoy erehw si
ssalc yrotsih morf ,newG dna htuR—
,ylprahs dias newG
,lartuen ylnrobbuts deniamer eciov s’ilE
,nihtyna detnuah a ro ,esuoh
.edis eht morf niatrec erom on dekool sgniht tub
,llew a ekil tlef tI
.lla ta drayevarg a saw siht taht ti rof drow s’ilE ekat ot dah evah dluow uoY
”?ereh gniht siht retnuocne yllautca ot ew era ylekil woH“
tnemeticxe reh nI
esuac sej—deid yeht erehw ro
.neB ot derepsihw htuR
”,gnihtaerb ruoy no gnisucof ekil si rohcna na naem uoY“
.denevnoc tsrif dah ruot eht erehw gnissorc daorliar denodnaba eht ot denruter d’yehT
.yawa wolb dna pu yrd ot ecalp elohw eht dna tsub ot mialc eht rof emit ni tsuj hcruhc eht nidliub dehsinif
,maeb thgilhsalf reh htiw edacaf gnidliub gnidnarts-eerf eht deddorp htuR
.ylmrif flesmih dlot neB
.deksa yllanif sivaD
,yawrood ytpme eht drawot hcrop a fo egde tnanmer eht revo deppets ylluferac ilE
.owt ro raey a nihtiw sdud eb’t tuo denrut ro pu deird rehtie yltsom d’etis eht dnuora derettacs smialc a-lufdnah eht
.elbatrofmocnu leef ot detrats neB llit tcatnoc eye suoires ,mrif dleh ilE ”.tcaer naC
,rohcna taht nisu peek nac yeht na
,ereh etelpmoc erom saw ssenkrad eht tuoba gnihtemoS
teiuq gib a gnieb sih rof tcepxe
”?eh t’nsi ,ediug ruot a rof ddO“
.thgiarts gniht eno nitteg er’ew
,tnorf tuo pukcip dlo detsur eht
”.erom on eno deen t’nseod ,ekil erom rO
”,dluow uoy dereggiF“
,edistuo retsaf spord erutarepmet esuac“
,snossel atuo teg ot ,esoprup no ti od d'stnedutS
detnuah A .deneppah nirebmemer s’ti revetahw erehw s’taht esuac
”!desruc teg ot gniggeb tsuj s’taht
.srebmemer ti sgniht dna won gnineppah r’sa sgniht neewt‘ ecnereffid eht llet t’nac
.rood nibac eht drawot mih dellup dna wap gnitsisernu s’ilE morf elttob eht detfil sivaD ”.wonk I“
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
sgnidliub neeb ecno dah taht snoteleks nedoow deyerg-nus eht neewteb ni
.tniop a dah tibbarkcaj eht dettimda kniks eht ,enim denodnaba eht dehcaer yeht nehW
,snoolas ,sehcruhc ,spohs ,semoh—
,rednow attog uoy esuac oslA
,nissap s’emit llet t'nac tsohg a
.siht gnillet eno eht erew ehs fi sa
.dne eht ta s’ytaK ytlaS
,elttil a depmuls tibbarkcaj ehT
”.snoitcartsid htiw pu nimoc syawla ydob a tog uoy nehw naht
,yrc tub nihton od sa tsohg a fo llet raeh semitemos od uoY
”,esnes sekam tahT“
.denodnaba saw ecalp eht erofeb neve detroper nieb saw sretnuocnE
,od ot gniyrt sej kcuts teg na ,daed er’yeht wonk t’nod sa mehT
detnuah eb nac nihtyna
naem ylirassecen t’nod tsohg A“
.nobruob yenoh fo elttob a decudorp
,ni dlohtoof a teg ot niyrt htrow eb d’ti thguoht
”’?rohcna‘ eht si noitanitsed eht
"?sretnuocne fo dnik tahW"
neeb evah ot thguo foor eht erehw ecaps eht hguorhT
.snosaes evitalumuc fo thgiew eht yb margolellarap a otni deweks sknalp elttirb
,tfel eht ot gnitsil saw erutcurts eritne eht dna retnec eht ni gnilkcub saw foor eht woN
.deksa ydobon tuB
.noitacol eht ni tneserp si sa tsohg a uoy steg—
,ti teg ot tuoba erew yeht nrows adluoc I“
ecalp eno ni syats taht tsohg a uoy teg lliw rohcna sa yromem A .on na sey ,lleW“
,regnol tol a ref
”.dnimreven ,tahw wonk uoY“
.ti ees ot krad oot saw ti
”.yadnoM ,ssalc ni uoy ees ll’I“
,nwod demlac s’tsiegretlop a fi tuB“
t’nia I .ma’am ,ekil uoy revetahw me llac nac uoY“
?tuo ti krow ot su detnaw eh“
.niaga morf draeh gnieb reven dna nivael ylneddus tsuj stsiegretlop tuoba raeh uoy yhw’S
.me fo lla ton ,lleW“
,evah ot diap d’yeht noitasrevnoc eht ot kcab tfihs ot ytinutroppo na was yltnerappa newG
,me ni ydobon t'nerew ereht nehw htrof dna kcab gnikcor sksed raeh dluow mramloohcs eht yldesopS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,tog uoy rohcna adnik tahw dnA
detelpmoc steg reven ksat eht nehT
.esuohloohcs deniur eht fo roiretni eht sa elbadaernu sa noisserpxe
dalg eb dluohs ew sseug I“
.efilretfa eht a’snoiger repeed oT
!t’ndid eh hcihw ,tsohg a eb ot demialc dah eh fi neve“
,gnihtaerb saw ti ekil leef TON did tI
,ilE mih llac tub
.gnipeew fo sruoh retfa semoc hcihw taht ekil mlac a tlef eh dna
.htrof dna kcab elttob eht ssap ot ylno devom yehT
.teg nac nosrep a sa lla ta nihton nieb ot esolc sa tuoba s’taht
”.aedi dab a tsuj si ni gnioG“
,evig ot denimreted saw ilE ruot fo dnik eht ot flesreh dengiser dah newG ekil dednuos ti
”.drayevarg eht s’pots txen ,yawynA“
,reverof yrgna yats t’nac nosrep nivil A
.yltnerappa ,hcrop tnorf eht no gnitiaw ffo dezod d’eH
!rekihhctiH lartcepS eht s’tahT !eno siht wonk I“
”,gnisucof fo gnikaepS“
,nepo seye sih peek ot thgif ot dah neB ”,lleW“
,erom on sesnes on tog s’ti ,sulP
,retfa esle nihtemos ot derohcna pu dniw yeht semitemoS
.ecnatsni ref odnanreH ydoolB ,srekihhctih lartceps rey ekaT
”,ereht kcart thgir eht no reY“
”sgnitnuaH ni nosseL A“ si yrots s’thginoT
”?tnuoc secnaes dnA“
.thgirpu ot esolc erutcurts eht fo tfel saw tahw dloh ot sporp sa sretfar desopruper dah enoemos fi sa dekool ti ,deedni—
fi sa gnileef a dna
,yldegella ,detnuah dna ,denodnaba eht erolpxE !ruoT gniklaW nwoT
.mih nekow dah tahw dna saw eh erehw ezilaer ot tnemom a sivaD koot tI
,htaerb reh rednu derettum newG
.ssenkrad eht otni dewollaws saw dna denrut ilE
,dnimreven llew
yllufepoh yeht neht
”,stsohg fo sdnik ereht erA“
…nizilaer ot esolc erew yeht thguoht
”?ssalg deniats fo stib gnidnif fo ecnahc yna s’ereht esoppus uoy“
retcennoc devapnu eht no ffo nrut ot uoy ksa ot eb lliw“
,etal gnikaeps yllacinhcet—
”.ti nitaeper peek yeht drah os efil morf yromem cificeps a no nisucof tsohg a
leoJ deman ediug a gnitcepxe neeb d’yeht hguoht neve
.sseldrager dedeecorp ilE
”.esu ot naem yllautca yeht enO
.sruoh naht rehtar sraey ereh neeb d’eh tlef tsomla eh tub
tsohG thgindiM - LAED LAICEPS
.noitanitsed rieht gnihcaer erofeb dehsinav ev’yeht dnif tub tfil a enoemos evig yehT
.deracs dnuos ton ot hguone delzzup dednuos eh depoh neB
:mih ot eman a tup nac uoy s’os
,ni peelsa nellaf d’eh gniws hcrop eht htaeneb relooc eht otni dehcaer sivaD
.meht otni elbmuts ot eb dluow sdraobroolf gnissim dna sretfar nellaf elbativeni eht dnif ot yaw ylno eht ereht ni krad os eb d’ti taht tsuj s’ti
”?os yas dna tuo ti erugif ot enoemos sdeen eh rO
.srekeeS me llac emoS
”!hguoht ,saw eh su dlot tub lla eH“
.tirips a tsuj s’taht ,ydob a tuohtiw
.evila llits erew nwot eht elihw neve nwod tuhs loohcs eht taht hcum os
:rohcna na fo elpmaxe cissalc a s’ereht woN
.yad eht ni kcab ,ytiroirp a neeb t’ndah senotsdaeh gnikam taht desseug neB
?eromyna yas dluoc ohw
,noteleks yna ekiL
,luos a tub ay ot nihton t’nia ereht nehw tpeC
,gniod s’tsohg eht nihtemos tnia rohcna esohw tsohg adnik eno s’ereht ,yawynA“ ,eugnot sih dekcilc ilE ”.diputs tsuj s’yeht ,ma’am ,lived eht fo tnia sesno-yaS“
.erom on senomroh ro srettimsnartoruen on tuohtiw snoitome pu retsum ot tluciffiD
:rohcna rieht sa ksat adnik emos nisu si tnanever A
,levarg no spetstoof fo dnuos eht saw ereht neeb reve d’eh ngis ylno ehT
.yawrood eht dnoyeb ,tfel roolf on saw erehT
.nikcor ksed a dnuos tsrif ta nidliub eht etaucave d'ehs os toG
,ruot siht nivig peek atfah ll’I ,neht lliT“
.rohcna na evah t’nseod sa“ ,derewsna ilE
,ogitrev ekil-uv-ajed
”,nuf dah I ,yeH“ .dias newG
”.ereht enog sah sa meht si erom uoy llet dluoc sa seno ylnO
”?yltcaxe ,esoht era tahW“
.htiw ssem ot sgniht etirovaf rieht a-eno saw drayevarg siht dnA
”.tog s’ti rohcna eht evah ot
,doots llits edacaf yrots-owt ehT
.gnol woh dias evah t’ndluoc eh tub
.sevil rieht ot pu dedda ,rehtegot tup
,tnemeticxe dehsuh lla saw eciov s’htuR ”,stnanever oS“
.erom on ereht tnia taht rab a dniheb namow a ees ll’uoy semitemos yas yehT“
kcab derats gnihtyna fI
,rof diap yeht tahw gnitteg yllaniF
nwaD eht fo thgiL ehT nI ni
.stoob gnikih sih fo tuo elggurts dnabsuh sih pleh ot tlenk sivaD ”.on tub
.dnuorg eht ta derats
sllaw eht did sa
,mih htiw gnorw nihton eb ot mees t’now ereht dnA .tsrif ta
.rac ruoy atni tel a-t’ndluohs ylbaborp uoy taht rekcuf nikool-yldnierfnu
htuos nivird er’uoy fi taht“
.sbrubus eht ni nemselas gnilevart
,tnecrep drennuh-eno ,yletulosba era eW
,thgindim tsap sruoh lareves saw ti esuaceb spahreP
.deknilb neB ”,onnud I“
.ni meht devaw dna
,ecitsuj ot thguorb emirc a niees ro
.niur dna tsud tub gnihton saw hcihw dnoyeb
.no evom dluohs ew“ ylno dias eh
.tnaem taht rohcna fo dnik tahw ksa dluow hcihw revo secnalg degnahcxe kniks dna ,rennurdaor ,tacbob ehT
,wonk uoy ,tsuj saw tI
,sehtolc ytsud ,amup giB
:yrotsih tub ereh nihtoN“
,thgin sselthgil tub selim rof gnihton saw ereht meht dniheB
“ yllis oot saw ti
”?stsohg ni detseretni er’lla’y taht detnarg ref ti ekat nac I esop’s I oS“  floWcaM boR yb ”sgnitnuaH ni nosseL A“   ot noitnetta tneiciffus yap yeht fi
.kniks eht ot kcab denrut neht
stneduts eerht esehT
dna yrotsih lacol emos teG
eloh eht morf ezeerb thgils a leef dluoc neB taht hguone raen tsuj saw ecnartne enim ehT
ot eporuE ni strac nwardesroh morf
.hgual gnigaruocne na eno taht evag—
,tnaem tibbarkcaj eht tahw ksa dluoc eh erofeb tuB