,elgnuj a saw ytic eht
.sevooh evah ot truh dluow ti hcum woh ta decniw tuaseL dna
,hctaP eht fo egde eht ot ssonS del tuaseL
.mroftalp eht fo dne rehto eht sdrawot mih gnillup
.yetam ,tnemevoM ehT pu evig ot syug eht ro uoy gniksa ton m'I
,sevil rieht htiw od ot retteb gnihton dah ohw smub erew yeht taht noitpecnocsim eht dah detsixe sruecarT eht wenk ohw esoht
,mih gnitsurt ni teb gib a nekat dah maiL
ti dnuof tevic eht dna ,mih dnuora lla gnikool llits saw esroh ehT
,dnuora lla stnecs elbignatni eht
.niart eht fo pot eht gnivael swap htob ,llew sa ffo dehsad tuaseL
.delbmurc krowkcirb eht fo trap dna
.ylekilnu naht erom erew epacse rehtona rof secnahc rieht dna
.seiralgrub no ylniam detsisbus dna
.sserdda laitnediser tnenamrep a deen lliw I tuB
.flesym ti deredisnoc t'nevah I kniht t'noD“
,dah reve ti naht redrah gnipmuht traeh siH
.mrala ni kcab deppets tuaseL dna
.renepmad larutan a enips dna ydob sih fo selcsum dehcterts eht
.taht rof trats gninnur a dedeen eh
tuaseL ”?dootsrednu taht sI
.dednuos ti suolucidir woh dezilaer neht ylno dna ,tuaseL deksa
.ereh fo tuo hguone ylkciuq evom ot elba eb t'ndluow eh
,)skooB affaJ yb dehsilbup ylremrof( snoitacilbuP laoG yb yrotciV ot yaW eht walC ni deraeppa ylremrof dah ”drawroF paeL A“
.srehto eht htiw ereh pu hsinif dna erif eht tuo tup ot tog ev'I“
.kcolb txen eht ta ecnartne noitats eht sdrawot ssonS htiw deggoj eH
,ayakS yb renroc eht ni dniheb tfel selttob reeb lareves dettops
gniliar a revo pael ro tluav ot retsaf saw ti
.kcab teef sih werht dna
.nodnoL ni kcab rennur a saw I ,si tnioP“
.emoh kcab teg ot gnihcti saw tuaseL dna
.ylkciuq pu dekrej daeh 'ssonS dna ,maiL deksa
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.tpek erew snoissessop yldlrow wef rieht erehw ot yvirp eb
”.ti ot mih taeb t'nod uoy fi uoy pmuj t'now tuaseL ;terf t'noD
”,uoy htiw enif s’ti fi ,worromoT“
,egairrac tsal eht otno tsrif-teef
.srae sih dekcilf arogna ehT
.nevorp dah gnirehtag yreve sa
.esnet waj dna ydob
.hcuorc a otni ylkciuq gnippord
.mih tsil ot derac neve eciffo ytic eht fi s’tahT
.yad txen eht sevil ruo morf enog eb ot ylno ,elihw a rof wenk ew ohw swollef dah lla ev’eW
tuaseL deksa ”?uoy htiw sgnignoleb...ruoy tog uoY“
,wolF eht ot flesmih dereviled
,tiusrup foor ni deniart tinu detacided eritne na tog
.detpecca saw ssel gnihton dna
,pmuht duol a htiw foor talf a no nwod thgiarts dednal eH
.meht hguorht yaw rieht gnikam ecilop demrofinu ruof fo maet a
.llaw wol eht fo esab eht tsniaga decarb toof thgir regnorts sih
.keew txen fo dne eht yb ecalp a teg ot dnetni I“ .yltrohs maiL dias ”,si tI“
ev'yehT .yllidacciP ot notgnisneK morf neeb ev'uoy fi wonk sreppoc eht os krowten lartnec a ni detcennoc si siht lla dnA
.flesmih rof ees dna nwod og ot ecnahc eht dah eh emit hcae fo tnesba eb ot demees
.gniht detsalb a od t'ndluoc I dna
.dah eh naht rewols hcum tiebla
tuaseL ”.emityad gnirud sned elbissop mih gniwohs ffo retteb er'uoy ;krad s’tI
.sevael eht gnoma seilferif ekil thgil fo stniop thgirb
enihcam gnidnev a otno dednal-pord eh ,sepip fo tuO
.drawrof dehsad ssonS tub tuaseL delley
”.kool a ekat ,ereH
ecafrus eht taht gnihtemoS
”,sesor fo deb a t'nia efil tub
thguoht yrev eht dneherpmoc ot thguof eh sa gnikcilf srae sih ,tuaseL dias
”.ti ot enod s'tnemnrevog doog eht tahw retfa
.delpmurc eh sa mih htaeneb gnilkcub teef
.kcab swalc sih delliw eh sa gninettalf ruf sih
.ni tes ti fo noitazilaer eht sa ffo deliart eciov siH
,ylivaeh dehgis tac ehT
.dehcterts liat dna sgel sih gnipeek
.reilrae dah ti sa dehsal regnol on liat siH .maiL dias
,sthguoht sih ot eciov evig ot deganam eh nehW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.edis eht ta sdlohtoof dna wap eht nwod ylwols yaw sih gnikam detrats dna
.ssonS gniteem seye ,pu dekool eH
,elpoep a erew yeht ereH
.yad rehtona pmuj ot evil t’ndluow eh ro
,gnivil doog dah eW
,mih deyaws smsirabrab s'ayakS neve toN
.deyonna eb tub pleh t'ndluoc tuaseL dna ,nosaer emos rof lufraef demees eH
,ssonS tsap tpael tevic ehT ”!rehtorb ,nuR“
,lennut eht fo slewob eht deretne niart eht sa gnikcud
,ecnatsid siht morF
.seiceps ro elytsefil ruoy etipsed
,smra sih dedlof
ecilop eht rof detrap dah dworc eht
.ekilhcus dna tnemevoM ehT fo selpicnirp gnidiug eht dewollof t'ndah su fo esoht esuac'
,mih rof t'nsaw ti dediced maiL fi dna ,flesruoy gnieb
.retirw yranecreM floW a si ohw
,nwod kcab tnes eb dluoc eh erofeb tsuj dna ,drah dellup ydob sih tsniaga ytivarg fo hctip railimaf ehT
.redluohs sih revo tuaseL delley
”?llor dab a morf siht saW“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.mih dniheb tuo dewolf enam sih sa ydob sih ot esolc dekcut sgel
s’tel ,tuaseL ,timmaD“
”?ecalp ruoy ot raf woh ,oS“
.elpoep fo ssam gnihsurc eht ni esolc ssonS peek ot gniyrt
”?ereh yaw eht no revird sub a ffo ssip uoy diD
,floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“ fo
.dexaler serutaef s'maiL dna ,tuaseL deksa
!niag lanosrep fo eman eht ni taht llA
.daeha sreciffo ecilop tisnart owt yb deteerg eb ot ylno
.klawedis eht no niats rehtona tsuj er'uoy
.tuaseL delworg ”!gniod era uoy tahw s'taht tuB“
tuaseL .yawa dekool eh sa gnitnilg seye sih fo srenroc eht ,desuap tac ehT ”...neht tuB
3 fo 2 trap
,namssenisub adnap a tsap gnigdoD
strap eerht fo dnoces eht eht saw sihT
,mroftalp eht ta pu dellup niart A
!tuaseL dna ssonS ot deneppah tahw tuo dnif ot
;cat-cit ro pmuj-llaw a rof ecaps t'nsaw erehT
,)ne=gnal?flowisakim/moc.rettiwt//:sptth(  floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“
.relykS fo eman eht yb rotnem a daH
.dlrow eht ni seitinummoc foor tsegral eht fo eno dah nodnoL taht htuom fo drow yb wenk
.sriatspu gnitiaw erom ylbaborp erew ereht ,tsap tog yeht fi neve dna ,mroftalp eht ssorca tuo sevlesmeht daerps dah sreciffo ecilop ehT
.hcrep sih no ylthgils dekrej eh sa dekcilf srae s'tuaseL
.ekoj a dekcarc deeR sa
.enola egatoof war eht morf knuks morf regdab llet t'nac uoy ;tihs ekil s'ytilauQ“
tuaseL .drawrof s’taht dna
,ti fo nuf eht rof tsuj em taeb dluoc meht fo eno ynA
,sgnag rednuorG lacol eht denioj srehto eht dna
.sneerg fo lufhtuom a neewteb ssonS dias
”.llaf dab a morf emac tI“
”.ereht yawbus eht edir ew fi dnim t'nod uoy epoh I os ,derit fo dnik m'I
reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.daeha raf epacsytic eht dehctaw yeht sa
selzzum degartuo dna dekcohs lareves fo espmilg a hctac ot emit hguone tsuj dah tuaseL dna ,delley sregnessap lareveS
.eye s’dnim sih ni ylkciuq gnivlove epacse fo seuneva
.seye sih gniknilb ,dehcterts
.woleb nwod srekoolno gnipag eht revo flesmih gnuws eh sa ylkciuq swap gnihctiws
,tuo yaw eno ylnO
”,tnemevoM ehT pu gnivig er'uoY“
?gniht a hcus od ruecarT yna dluow yhW
”-mret gnorts a si 'pu gnivig' ,kooL“
,ereht llits erew deeR dna nushA ylnO
.raef was tuaseL ,seye sih nI
.sriap ni dekrow sruecarT emos yhw snosaer eht fo eno saw tI
.sroolf tnereffid no smroftalp tnereffid htiw etelpmoc
,yticolev ria fo ssol neddus eht ni drawrof dekrej
.morf emoc dah eh erehw ot kcab stops sih teg ot mih dlot ohw enoemos yb netaeb tog tsomla dna ,steerts eht gniklaw deirt dah tuaseL ecnO
.ylfeirb sdap desuollac s'maiL deppirg eH .tuaseL dias
)moc.yellavtibbar.www//:sptth( sserP yellaV tibbaR yb 0D3%egap62%52D3%rebmun_nruter62%hsarTB2%yrruFD3%txet_hcraesF3%php.hcraesF2%moc.yellavtibbar.wwwF2%F2%A3%sptth=lru_nruter&9089=meti?php.meti/moc.yellavtibbar.www//:sptth  .sserP yellaV tibbaR yb hsarT yrruF dna
,spmuj gninnur ni htgnerts rieht saw setelhta rehto morf sesroh detarapes taht gniht enO
,tuoba gninrut seye sih ,teiuq saw ssonS
tuaseL ”?naem uoy od revetahW“
.kcats yenmihc a tsniaga ylivaeh denael maiL
.kcab kool a decnahc dna
,don a htiw teef sih ot pu kcab tog eH .ti eb os
.yltnereffid desserd dna dekool uoy esuaceb tsuj uoy noitseuq ot ecilop rof ycnednet ehT
sevom eht htiw lla
,dellik neeb evah thgim eh stnelat sih rof t'nerew ti fI
,bmilc enola tel ,klaw ot gninrael dlihc a fo snoitom ykrej eht dah esroh ehT
egde foor eht otno dleh ylevitcnitsni eH
,thguac tog su fo wef A“ .delruc pil siH
.enola ti og ot dah eh sezilaer eh ecno cinap ylerus dluow dik eht ro ,ssonS deniojer eh taht tnatropmi saw ti tuB
.yltpurba dedne sfoor eht ro ,denaw ygrene sih nehw emit a emac syawla ereht tub
”?gniog teg ot ydaeR .ssonS ,oY“ .ti ni devom dna devil eno sa ,fleseno dnuora tnemnorivne eht ot dednetxe osla tcepseR
,ecnats evisnefed a otni yletaidemmi deppord tub teparap a tsniaga sdrawkcab dekrej
.srehto gniniart ot timmoc ot emit eht dah ohw sruecarT ynam t'nerew ereht taht dezilaer eh ,ekops eh sa neve tuB
ruf rieht revo hsaw ezeerb thgin looc eht tel dna tis dluoc yeht erehw egdel a dnuof tuaseL dna maiL ”.ecaeP“
,eldnah ot tuaseL rof hcum oot saw taht dna ,neve suoretsiob
.etercnoc eht tsniaga liat sih deknik eh sa decniw eH
”,uoy desucca I taht yrros ma I dnA“
.thgil ecnanetniam lanoisacco eht fo hsalf eht morf gnitruh seye sih
,drawrof delwarc eH
,evom enola tel ,no dloh ot troffe na koot tI
,boj a gnirud sreppoc yb nwod tohs tog flesmih rotnem doog eht nehW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
tac eht ot sdrawot denrut ssonS woN ”...maiL tuB“
tuaseL .derab swalc dna sgnaf ,delrans eh sa tuo gniffulf ruf sih ,tuo dehsal maiL
suoivbo ylgnikatsniap os saw ti hguoht neve ,dnuora teg ot tnemevoM ehT gnizilitu enoyna tsniaga os saw enoyrevE
”?thgirla ,swap ym morf pmuj tsuJ“
.ruoh-flah doog a rof ereht fo tuo esra ym teg t'ndluoc dna yella nmad eht otni deppord I
emoc yeht sa sgniht ekat I taht gniksa tsuj m'I
.wap ni tnemucod a detlusnoc lwocs a dna sepirts eerht htiw tnaegres netram enip a
.su fo tuo gnihtemos ekam dluoc eh deveileb eh dna ,neht erofeb sbuc sselemoh ahcnub a erew eW
.tniop gnirehtag rieht ot pmuj eht ssorca maiL dewollof eh tuB
”.siht lla naht efil retteb a eb ot tog s’ereht
,rehtegot meht tpek tahw saw yhposolihp ehT
?tuoba deirrow uoy era tahw tsuJ“
,meht tsap dehsup seuh dna stnecs lla fo srelevarT
.foor eht ot kcab ylhtooms gnidils ,deksa eh
.ytic niam eht fo noitcerid eht ni yleugav derutseg maiL ”?skcolb eerht
,deifisnetni saw mih ssorca gnihsur ria eht fo ecrof eht ,ereH
,tnecsed sih ni enif gniod saw ssonS erus ekam ot sdnoces wef yreve pu dekool eH
.meht ot emac thgin eht fo sdnuos eht ylno dna ,ria eht ni delgnim yruf dna raef fo
,ecaep eht pu evig dluoc maiL woh derednow
,enil niart yticretni eht ot pu deknil hcihw noitats tisnart a saw sihT
.maiL deiduts eh sa ediw seye ,tuaseL dias
.srehto eht sa dedworc sa ylraen t'nsaw ti os ,yawa snoitats evif tuoba tcirtsid s'rekrow eht ta
,mih tsap deltsihw egairrac a fo dne eht sA
.yas ot dehsiw eh sdrow eht mrof ot thguof eh sa kcab dleh tub ,semit lareves htuom sih denepo
.ti ot nwod emac ti nehw sgnidliub dna steerts worran nihtiw aibohportsualc neve
”.ereh sdrawot pihs eht no yadhtrib ym dah I tcaf eht tnuoc uoy fi ,neetxiS ?ereh emac I nehw neetfif saw I uoy gnillet em rebmemer uoY“
.ssonS esroh eht rotnem ot deksat saw dna
emoh kcab seilimaf rieht tuoba gnittahc
.laem sih no gnipmohc ssonS
s'ti dias relykS tub
dehgien ”!erofeb taht enod t'nevah I tuB“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy
,teef ralucsum owt htiw ffo dehsup eh
tuaseL ”,uoy teg ot tuo s'enoyreve toN .rehtorb ,xaleR“ .ssonS htiw
,won yB .esroh eht ot pu dehsad dna hcrep sih morf nwod tpael eH
.mih koot raef erofeb ssonS ot teg ot dah tuaseL tub
.dniheb esolc gniwollof ssonS ,enil ytefas eht edisgnola dehsad eh
,tnemevoM ehT fo elpicsid a saw eh tuB
tnecs ehT .deneppah tsomla tahw dezilaer yeht sa gnitnap htob
”...ti rof gniksa neeb yltcaxe t'nevah stneilc ruoY“ .deksa eh
tuaseL ”!enif eb ll'uoy dna uoy ekat wolF eht tel tsuJ“
.leciC ,rehtorb elttil sih ot saw eh ralimis woh yb desirprus saw tevic eht dna
.semit lla ta mih woleb teef evif gnipeek
?meht retfa sreppoc eht era yhW
dednal tevic eht sa ,deziremsem
.egnar lausiv fo tuo er'uoy nehw uoy yfitnedi ot
.ssonS rotnem ot uoy deen I .em draeh uoY“
.yaw rehto on ti evah dluow eh dna
.ylkciuq dloh sih deniager esroh eht tub
tuaseL .gninetsil ,yb esolc tas ssonS sa
.thgin eht rof pik nac uoy erehw uoy wohs ot dereffo tuaseL lap yM
.erifpmac eht ta kcab
,nrut eht rof dewols niart ehT
nwod daeh sih gnipeek
,tnedifnoc erom saw leciC taht saw ecnereffid ehT
.smitciv fo tsil gnol a ni citsitats rehtona tsuj
;taht fo hcum kniht t'ndid
.timrep krow a rof noitacilppa ym gnissecorp dehsinif tsuj dah yeht taht yadretsey em demrofni eciffo noitargimmi ehT
,ssonS ot kcab denrut tevic ehT
”,em ot swen…s'tahT“
,mottob eht dehcaer yeht emit eht yb dessap dah setunim neT
.ecneirepxe gninethgirf dna elbidercni na htob saw tI
rehto hcae dellabeye maiL dna eH
yreve ecno tsap emoc uoy smac teerts esoht wonk uoY“
.ylregnig detpecca ssonS hcihw ,parw eiggev a dna ekoc eht mih thguob tuaseL dna ,nevelE-7 a dessap yehT
.elims a gnicrof ,tuaseL dias
.dnuorg yb gnillevart detah eh yhw fo dednimer saw tuaseL niaga ecno dna
,wap eno htiw epip a otno gnihctaC
,revewoh ,epip tsal eht no pirg sih tsol eH
,laeh ot detrats dah ti yaw eht yb dlo skeew owt tuoba dekool tI
,noitats eht ot spets eht nwod tnew yeht sa
,elpoeP fooR rehto eht htiw gniteem ylhtnom a dednetta tuaseL ,emit tsaL
!tnempoleved dna htworg-fles pu gnivig er'uoY“
.thgin eht fo ecnelis eht ni demmuh ciffart thgiL
.ynitsed dna snoisiced nwo ruo enimreted enola ew tub
dna gnilaets fo hguone dah I
,niart eht edisgnola nur ot kcab denrut tevic ehT
,slaitini s’rehtorb sih fo srettel dessobme owt ehT
.esle enoyreve ekil llaf a fo ecrof eht etapissid ot llor a mrofrep ot deen t'ndid maiL
,pu nettog tsuj dah esroh eht taht ylno gniees
,nmaD .yllufraef mih ta kcab dekool ssonS dna
,deneppah gnihtyna fi dna
,rorroh sih ot dna ,noitats txen eht ot gnidael nrut a saw meht fo daehA
.nees yldrah ,ereht syawlA
.talf srae sih htiw tuo dehtaerb maiL
.elkcuhc a htiw dias
,uoy dnatsrednu t’ndid ohw srehto morf regnad ehT
.gniliec s’noitats eht gnignahrednu sepip fo seires a ot pu gnignirps ,egaggul sih pota waptoof a demmals eh
.htaed sih ot degnulp rehtorb sih sa neve
”?su htiw gnimoc uoY“
tuaseL .rehto hcae htiw dah sruecarT eht fo emos tnemugra na yb ylno detautcnup ecnelis gnol a saw erehT
,hcuorc-flah a ni dnuora nups tuaseL
”?gnihtyreve si yenom kniht uoy oD
.ygoloedi tnereffid a ni tnemevoM ehT yllaitnesse saw ti tub ,gninnur-
,ni ekat ot hcum os saw erehT
egde foor eht nopu swap sih decalp eH
,gnorw enog noisses gniniart a rof tnuhnam a detaitini ecnis dah ecilop ehT
.mroftalp eht ssorca gnidnuoser leets no sfooh fo gnab duol eht htiw egairrac eht fo pot eht ot delias ssonS
.noitats eht fo tuo gnillup detrats dah niart eht dna
saw tnemevoM ehT fo rewollof a gnieb taht ,revewoh ,wenk eH
,sruecarT enilef rehto ekiL
,won thgir taht wenk esroh eht taht
”!ssonS ,ti od t'noD“
.tnemevoM ehT tuoba wenk I lla srehto alpuoc a dna em thguat eH
,floWisakiM yb ”drawroF paeL A“:yojne esaelP
.did eh sa kcirb eht ssorca swalc sih gnirocs
,evom ot elbanu ,sretspmud eht gnoma ereht gniyl ekil s’ti tahw wonk t'nod uoY
.ti gnildnah fo yaw nwo rieht dah nosrep hcae tub ,raef s'maiL dnatsrednu etiuq t'ndid tuaseL ”.level dnuorg no
/flowisakim/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:sptth floWisakiM/ikiw/moc.rufikiw.ne//:sptth egap ytiniffaruF ro rufikiW sih no seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoy dna
.ti dnuora klaw naht rehtar
.mih sdrawot detarelecca foor eht sa kcab ti thguof tuaseL
”?thgirla ,ekoc a uoy yub ll'I ,dnuorg eht ot teg ew nehW .ssonS ,no emoC“
,niart eht etisoppo yltcerid nmuloc eht pu nar tuaseL ,lley a htiW
.esu regnessap rof t'nsaw siht taht detacidni draob cinortcele eht ta ecnalg a tub
tuaseL ,drawrof detrad netram eht tnemom ehT
,sthgil thgirb dna sesion duol eht lla htiw
,mih sdrawot kcab sih denrut tac eht tuB
.segairrac eht neewteb ecnaraelc eht otni gnihctip
,dehctaw ecilop ehT
,ffo trihs sih dellup maiL
.lluks dna ydob sih ni enob yreve tuohguorht detarebrever taht niart eht fo esion gninefaed ydaerla eht htiw gnola
ecilop htiw gnimeet ylekil saw noitats txen ehT
,swap dna teef sih no thgiarts dednal eh ,rehtaR
.daeh sih hguorht gnihsur sthguoht fo sdnik lla ,detatiseh tuaseL ”.su ekil evil ot snaem ti tahw ,sepor eht mih wohS
.mih nopu seitivitca s’yad gnol eht fo thgualsno eht leef dluoc eh ydaerlA
.nworf a otni gnisaerc ksam sih fo kcalb eht
dluoc tuaseL dna ,lennut eht fo ssenkrad eht ot ylkciuq detsujda yehT
,elbatrofmocnu os maiL nees tuaseL dah yleraR
”?niaga taht s’tahW“
.dias yllanif tac eht
,detatipaced teg eh tsel
.thguorb sfoor eht modeerf dna ,ytiliuqnart
.ytic eht ni neeb yllautca dah eh gnol woh derednow tuaseL dna
dezilaer tevic eht ,tloj a htiw dna ,erofeb morf ruof fo puorg eht erew mih dniheB
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.noos emitemos rewohs a ekat ot deen dluow eh derugif eH
”!niart eht fo pot eht ot uoy gnitsoob m’I ,dnuora nrut dna pots I nehW“
tnatropmi saw tI .kcab delrans
,yddub tuaseL ,si tcaf ehT“
,daeha pu ssonS was eH
”?timrep krow a deen uoy dluow yhw dnA“
tuaseL .hgual t'ndid eH
.sdrow rof tsol eh saw reven dna
”!yako ,flesym truh I“
.dnuora gnitteg ta doog os saw eh taht tcaf eht rof t'nerew ti fi
,dnik ruo rof ecalp on s'nodnoL
.nellows niamer tey
.tfel dna pu I os hguone dah d'I tub
,redluohs eht no ssonS gnikcamS
.gninnigeb tsuj saw ti
.niart eht ffo mih pir ot gninetaerht
eerF ti dellac yeht ,ereht revO
a tog dna tneilc ym ot ti edam I os ,elihw a retfa deppots niap ehT
.krow s’yad eht morf derit m’I esuaceb tsuj pets a ssim ot hsiw ton od I tub
.od ot dednetni eh tahw was tuaseL
.tcirtsid dlo eht ni htuos selim ynaM“
.nam ,struh ydoolb tI
.ereh pu uoy gum annog s'eno on ,xaleR“
,tol eht fo tsellams ehT
”,efas erehwemos meht dehsats I ,oN“
”.krow ot gniog yldrah si 'foor elbatius yna' nwod gnittuP
.rettam taht rof boj yad a dah nushA ekil emos dna ,stcartnoc yreviled dah yehT
,ria eht hguorht yllufituaeb delias esroh eht dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.rehtegot deppuc swap
tuaseL .yliraw ssonS deksa
tuaseL ,meht dnuora ecaps nepo eht ta hgis a gnivaeH
.tfel ydaerla dah syug rehto eht fo tsom taht hctaP ehT no ecnelis llarevo eht morf dezilaer dna
.yhw mih llet neve t’ndluoc I dna
.latem detniap eht ffo gnippils spitfooh
ereh tub ,tnemugra rieht devloser ydaerla dah hctaP ehT no sruecarT ehT
.yb esolc gniklaw srehto evah tey dna
”?ko ,sgnieb dezilivic ekil klat s’tel—
.pu kcab doots tuaseL sa tuo wap thgir sih htiw yldemahsa doots eH ”?ecaeP
srae s'tuaseL truh sleehw eht fo muh ehT
.tnemesacne eht tsniaga swalc sih deppat
ev'yehT .eromyna ton tub ,taht ekil hcet evah ot desu nodnoL
.segairrac eht fo krej eht rof etasnepmoc ot drah liat sih dehsal tuaseL dna
.pihsrotnem ot timmoc retteb nac I ,stcartnoc yreviled ssel gnitteg em htiw taht kniht yam emoS
.taht rof tsuj siraP evael ot dah eh dna
.tevic eht ta ylsuoires dekool maiL
tuaseL .nepo eht ni tuo erew yeht ylneddus dnA
,thgirpu delbmarcs eH
.ereh taob tsrif eht thguac I os ,nur eht no efil
.tuaseL dniheb dexif ezag sih htiw yawa gnikcab
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.lworg a kcab tib dna
.ni dexob yllanif saw eh
”?trats I od nehw ,oS“
txen eht ,yug rehto eht sa efil fo lluf sa eb yam uoy yad enO“
kcalc duol a htiw ylroop dednal eH
”.ereh era spoc eht ,tihS“
,tsap delkcirt sdnoces eht sa
,tuaseL ,lortnoc ruo dnoyeb ytic eht tuoba tol a s'erehT
.did eh sa ylkciuq gninnips ,teef sih ot tpael tuaseL dna ,esroh eht deinnihw
,elpmaxe sih dewollof dah ssonS
.elknit dna gnab duol a htiw pilf daehrevo sih ekorb teef sih ,cra lacitrev a ni sdrawnwod gninnipS
.doog saw taht tub
.tnemevoM ehT fo yhposolihp eht tsniaga gnieb ti fo nosaer eht rof ytinummoc eht ni meht fo yna wolla reven dluow maiL tub ,spahrep ,emoS
.ti tcepser ot dewov tuaseL dna
htrim ni sedis rieht gnihctulc ,ylduol dehgual sruecarT eht dna maiL
.ecnadiova eb ot demees ti ,esac s’maiL nI
,etal gnieb rof tuc yap
,ned ym ot kcab yaw eht lla nur ot gnirar er'uoy erus m'I dna ,snoitatimil ruoy gniwonk si tnemevoM ehT fo traP“
.erehwyreve deyarps ekoc sa sretummoc rehto eht fo slrans eht htiw gnola
sevom citsiretcarahc ruoy ezylana dna ,DH lluf ni ruf ruoy fo dnarts yreve serutpac taht syekcihood tog won
,syawla sa tsuj ,gnidliub txen eht hcaer ot retneC evitartsinimdA eht fo edis eht ffo gnipmuj-llaw saw I“ .maiL deifiralc
nosaer elpmis eht rof rehtona eno detcepser taht ytinummoc a
.mih no kcab peerc ot detrats siraP ni kcab tnedicni eht fo yromem eht ydaerlA
.llaw eht morf yawa cra na ni gnippilf ydob sih
.rac txen eht ot ffo flesmih decarb eh erofeb ssalg dekcarc eht hguorht
rehtar ro—srednuorG ynaM
.gnivil dnuorg fo
”,ytic eht dnuora teg ew woh ediced t'nseod maiL“
.emoh s'uluS amaM ni gnihctaw derebmemer eh seidemoc hcnerF eht sa lacimoc sa
.dnim sih hguorht dehsalf htaed s'rehtorb sih fo seiromem
,denettalf yeht sa neve
.taht tuoba yrros m'I“
,revo dekconk yeht elpuoc esuom a fo tsetorp fo slaeuqs eht derongi eH
.rorret ni nepo ediw seye ,ssonS
enil eht fo dne eht ot del mroftalp rieht ta ecivres niart ehT
.daeha segairrac owt pac rotalitnev a dniheb gnirewoc ssonS ees
hcneb a ta flesmih gnittis erofeb ylsuorogiv flesmih dehcterts
.denediw seye 'ssonS ”.wonk uoy ,tif gnipeek sa
.pu saw gnihtemos wenk
”—tnaw uoy fi siht rof yap nac I ,kooL“
.ffirdim sih evoba tsuj ruf kciht eht otni tuc dah taht
,thgirpu gnidnats ssonS ees ot emit ni tsuj
ruecarT a eb ot ton woh fo elpmaxe tcefrep eht eb dluow tuol tahT
.sruecarT gniniamer eht ot kcab denrut dna dennirg maiL
.tac eht ot kcab denrut ylkciuq eh dna kcab dekool ,.M.C
tuaseL ,niaga ecno dna ,meht ot ylno degnoleb taht dlrow a saw ti ,ereh pU
,thgiarts kcab doots eh sa yawa derednaem lworg s'maiL
,ria eht hguorht delias eh sA
,tuaseL dias ”,taht ton s'tI“
.dehsal liat s'maiL
.tius dewollof eh dna
,sepip wef txen eht ot drawno mih yrrac pmuj sih fo mutnemom eht tel eh
,semitemoS .meht ekil tsuJ
,laudividni euqinu a saw enoyreve taht
.ereht fo tuo tekcit rieht saw ti dezilaer neht eh dna
.lluf ydaerla saw niart eht ;rednow oN
”?maiL ,rettam eht gnihtemoS“
.waj sih tes ydaerla dah maiL
.selpicnirp eht fo enon tub
,daeh sih detlit
.kcen sih dnuora ralloc citsale eht morf gnignah tnadnep eht dedaenk sregnif siH
tnatropmi sa tsuj si peelS
,sboj suoiverp no desab seirotirret niatrec ot sthgir eht revo thguof emoS
.gnirps a ekil pu kcab ydob sih decrof eh sa thgirpu gnihsup
,mih wols ot tuo wap a hcaer ot flesmih gnicarb ,ezorf tuaseL dna epip esool a tsniaga delbmuts ssonS
,mroftalp eht ot sriats eht ta sretummoc eht ssorca gnitapissid evaw a ees dluoc eH
.egdelwonk lacidem cisab emos tuohtiw sfoor eht no gnol tsal t'ndid eno dna
,dedilloc fooh eht fo segde hguor eht sa yllufniap kcub sregnif sih tlef tuaseL .rotnem sih sdrawot fooh a gnitfil ,tpael eh sa dehgien ssonS
fo trap dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”...ro nushA ro flesruoy ton yhW ?em yhW“
,noisulcnoc eht rof emit txen ni enuT
,seirujni ot regnarts on erew elpoep lla fo sruecarT
”,level dnuorg ot gnivom m’I“
stlew yrgna lareves ees dluoc tuaseL ereht dna
.ti gnibruc revo lla erew sreppoc nodnoL eht tub ,modeerf tuoba lla s'tnemevoM ehT ,lleH
,yad taht netae t'ndah ylsuoivbo eH
,ruf s’tuaseL tsniaga deteffub dniw ehT
.yltneitapmi tuaseL dias
.su fo tser eht rof warts tsal eht saw ti
.thginot rof tsael ta ,ecalp ruoy ta ni deb ssonS tel nac uoy gnipoh m'I“
,efil fo yaw siht ot noitacided nwo sih gniwonk etipsed
srehto tel ot eno rof tsurt fo laed taerg a koot ti dna ,modeerf rieht sa hcum sa tsomla ycavirp rieht deulav sruecarT
.senigne fo zzub gnidne-reven a
,reverof sfoor eseht nur dluoc eh tlef eh
.draw sih gniracs ni dedeeccus ylno eh dna ,rehtorb gib a eb ot gniyrt saw eh ereh
,ytic eht fo muh eht raeh dluoc eh ereht morf dna