.ykcutneK ni noitats a rof ,emit eno eceip ffulf a diDÒ
,tneserp eht ni kcaB
.htaerb reh dleh wodaeM
.ton erÕuoY .suoitibma sÕeH
.sesion ykoops gnikam saw
.ylikahs detsisni wodaeM
.spil reh ot kcep ytniad a dereviled biF
?deb eht taht saw rO
,retupmoc reh ot kcab gninruT Ó.teews woHÒ
Ó.rehtaew lamron tsuj sÕtI
,kcab sih pu swap reh dils wodaeM
,ylleb reh no dedlof swap dna wollip a no daeh ,kcab dial ehS
.euqisyhp rednels ,ecin a htiw
.mih revo deklat ehs tub
.evol ni gnieb fo ecneirepxe ehT
.yrots elgnis ,gnidliub yzoc A
.ecap eht pu depmar biF Ó!retsaFÒ
.htuom reh fo tuo enilanerda fo etsat eht teg thgim ti tub
,welf ruF .teews dna kcilS
Ó?uoy lliw ,em fo derit teg reve tÕnow uoy É uoY .biFÒ
.kcen dna ecaf reh gnison ,pu desae biF
.tsig eht gnitteg yllanif ,dias wodaeM
.etarepsed dna detcartsiD
.siht ekil tuo detratsÑ
Ó,odanrot a eb ot gniog ton sÕerehTÒ
.taht yas tÕnoDÒ .deooc biF Ó,hctocsrettuBÒ
.tlih a ot demmals biF
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.tuo llup ot decrof saw eh ,pmil gniworG
.etal oot saw ti tuB
.xes reh drawot dna ,hgiht a dnuora
Ó É tahWÒ .derepsihw biF
.rethgil sedahs wef a saw ÕdlogÔ sih hguohT
Ó.esuoh eht fo edistuo eht no É ecnartne eno ylno sÕerehT
.liat reh rof dehcaer wap A Ó.rehto eht ot
.reh rof dias arteP Ó?oot ,em evol uoYÒ
Ó!tnemesab a evah neve tÕnod IÒ
Ó,esuom a ot yawetag eht
.elims elttil ,ytrilf a htiw dias biF
.em esol reven llÕuoYÒ
.egar etarepsed a ni ,yldaM .won ,gnilwoh saw dniw ehT  .hcaer ot drah
,gniunitnoc erofeb etunim a rof revocer reh tel eH
.rettoh tlef moor ehT
,htaerb reh gniniager llitS  .delgguns yeht
Ó.sessap ti litnu mrots eht ffo dnim ruoy peek ot gniht eht tsuj evah I ,ylikcuLÒ
.seitilibissop eht gniraef pots attog tsuj uoY
.llits reh peek ot smra reh no swap sih gnittup ,reh ot tnew ylkciuq eH
.xodarap a saw tI
,ecaf reh ot dellips taeh ehT
.68-espylacopA puorg tar sÕ0891 eht fo
?gniyas dlo taht wonk uoY .ecnatsni rof ,srae eht ekaT .mmh-
,mih dnuora dehcnelc ehS
.dias wodaeM Ó,yad taht ssalc dessim evÕtsuMÒ
.dne eht dehcaer reven ehS
ÓnoitcartsiD elttiL AÒ saw sihT
Ó?mMÒ Ó.odanrot eht sÕeh ebyaM
!yako eb ot gniog erew yehT
,hO !tlem thgim ehs tlef ehS
.noisseforp sih detius tI
.pmal eht ffo dehctiws eH
,nwod mih gnirb smra reh tel biF
.dessap dÕyeht nehw meht morf ti detirehni dÕehS
.noitom htooms ,ysae nA
,noitcafsitas htiw gnitnurg ,biF
si yrots sÕyadot dna
hAÒ .enohp reh rof hcaer ot detrats ehS
.ni kcab dehsur dna gninepo na desnes sraef sÕwodaeM
,namrehtaew a sÕeHÒ
.deksa wodaeM Ó?evac a ni reve uoy erew nehWÒ
.odanrot eht sÕeHÒ
,deunitnoc tar eht
.regnol evivrus em depleh evÕthgiM
Ó.lrig dooGÒ .dehtaerb ehs
.ton erÕuoY .VT no sÕeH
!gnikrow tÕnsaw tI
Ó?fo diarfa mÕI esle tahw wonk uoYÒ
.gnihsem ruf ,hsulf seidob
,etitep eht ,enohptrams reh ta nwod gniratS .tap-tap-a-taP
.noitadnuof sti no kaerc esuohmraf citsur ,dlo eht gnikam
,moor eht dellif wolg eiree nA !HSALF Ó É haeYÒ
.yerp sti mÕI dnA .rotaderp a ekiL
Ó?Õlavivrus mrotsÔ rof dohtem siht esu ot sreweiv ruoy llet ot gniog uoy era ,heh É erAÒ
.deb fo tuo deppoh
ÓnoitcartsiD elttiL AÒ
?ew diD .deknilb wodaeM
,tnedor rehto eht ta liat reh gnitniop ,dias ehs
.gnidne eht tuoba tÕnsaw ti esuaceb maerd mrots taht fo dne eht dehcaer reven dÕehS
.ssenkrad ot denruter moor ehT
mMÒ Ó?haeYÒ Ó.seitimertxe eht htiw trats attog eWÒ
É enif eb ot gniog saw gnihtyrevE
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.denaom dna dehcra ehS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.ffo gniliart ,dehgis wodaeM
.pirt eht ekam ot ylbbow oot erew seenk reH
Ó É tsuj I .wonk I .yrroSÒ
,taeb a deppiks ehS
.tsehc dekan sih ffo gnidils steehs eht
ytic eht fo sehcaer nrehtron eht ni ecalp yknaws a desael
?wonk uoY .evac a ekil si ecapslwarc ehTÒ
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dewolla arteP Ó,esuom a rof
.nway dehtootkcub a saw erehT Ó É tahWÒ
.gnilbmert saw ehS
,dias biF Ó,tsrif seidaLÒ
.pu ekaw dÕehs neht dnA
.dnuora denrut dna deknilb wodaeM
.tsrif ta sehcni wef a tsuJ
Ó É doom eht gnillik rof dnAÒ
.yggorg saw eciov sÕesuom tsevrah elam ehT
.evom txen sih tuoba kniht reh gnikam ,avluv reh nwod dna pu gnivom snalg ,reh desaet eH
Ó.hcum os uoy evol I
,reh rof ti od ot dediced wodaeM
.wollip reh no tuoba gnitsiwt daeh
?retsbiF ot detaler eb thgim smaerd ruoy taht kniht revEÒ
.ylthgit mih degguh dna
seye eulb reh dedleihs wodaeM
Ó!keEÒ .desnet wodaeM !MOOB !HSALF
spsaw ereht erAÒ Ó.spsaw etaH !spsaw rOÒ
.kcans thgindim a rof nehctik eht ot daeh ot
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
Ó.saw ereht fi yzarc gniog eb dluow enohp yMÒ
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK mÕI
.gnilialf liat reh
,dias biF Ó?hctocsrettuBÒ
.shtaerb sih erew raeh dluoc wodaeM llA .selbbin luferac
.roolf doow ,looc eht no gnippals swap-toof knip ,sselruf
Ó.rehtegot gnieb su rof elbisnopser erÕuoy
.rewolf reh gnissik saw kcoc sih litnu
.tnecs ym ,eciov yMÒ
Ó,etah uoy gniht eno sÕereht fi dnA .pu ti dekool IÒ
?gniht meetse-fles a sÕti ebyaMÒ
.nepo kcab deppans seye sÕwodaeM !MOOB
Ó.pu owt uoy tes I dalg llits mÕIÒ
Õ.retcarahcÔ dah esuoh eht tnaem taht yas ylbaborp dluow biF
.mih ta enohp reh dehsalf
Ó.esrow neve leef em sekam tsuj tahTÒ
.stnialpmoc on dah wodaeM tub
.deb reh ot dekool dna ,deknilb
.dewollaws ehS
.no dehctiws pmal A
.stneitap sÕruoh tsrif eht fo selif eht pu gnillup saw ehS
É ti gnithgif pots dluohs uoy woH
,rehto hcae dleh yeht
.deticilosnu yllausU
.latnemele dna waR
egnaro dna der fo llaw gnicanem a dewohs ppa rehtaew eht ta ecnalg rehtonA
!HSALF .dehsinif ehs
wen A .nwod dekool ehs ,biF gnirewsna fo daetsnI
tlef ehs ,nwod gniyal nevE
,deksa wodaeM Ó?tahw ekiLÒ
attog uoy gniyas toN
.sraef fo tsil a htiw pu emoc ot gniyrt ,dias biF Ó,ecnatsni rof ,ekiLÒ
deddorp dna desaet pit ehT
Ó,em ot era uoYÒ Ó É ton mÕIÒ
sllab yzzuf ,egral sih ,nooS
.sraet reh ta gnissik
saera gnitarepo dna gninaelc eht otni tnew ehs nehT
,esuoM .T dleiF yb
.esaeler rof deen etulosba na
.ti dekorts eh ,detsif-esolC
.dehsulb esuom ehT
detpmet-flah saw wodaeM
Ó.ereh teg yeht erofeb gninetsil ... ÕysaeÔ
.uoy seifirret ti dna ,ti toorpu ot gninetaerht dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
É dne eno morf ,woNÒ
Ó.cit suovren a llits sÕti tub ,etuc sÕti ,detnarGÒ
.daeh reh derewol wodaeM
É yad eht ni reilrae dneirf reh htiw dah dÕehs noitasrevnoc a dellacer wodaeM
.stsaerb reh nopu gnitser wap a ,dias biF
Ó É haeYÒ .deddon wodaeM
Ó!?esuoh eht stih odanrot a fi tahWÒ
.yteixna htiw yzzid
.detcartsid erom neve reh gnikaM
.gniog tpek arteP tuB
,deunitnoc arteP
Ó.yako sÕtI .su tsuj sÕtIÒ
Ó?relloh yknoh a ekil kool siht seod ,lriGÒ
.ytivitisnes htiw gnilzzis
,wodaeM Ó?yako uoy erAÒ
eciMÔ ?scisyhp fo wal eno taht draeh uoy tÕnevaHÒ
naem tÕnseod tem ew nehw moor emas eht ni gnieb ,niagAÒ
.gnirevaw eciov ,dedaelp ehs
?peels tuoba gnihtyna dias ohWÒ
,seye reh desolc wodaeM
Ó,sevlesruo ot pit taht peek ot su tnaw dluow CCF eht kniht IÒ
.revetahW .tÕnod ro ,trapa eviL .edud eht yrram
,ti ssik dna htuom ot ni denael eH ?rehto ehT .eno deldnof eH
.shtaerb deggar wef a koot ehS
.swap reh deppord wodaeM
Ó.egelloc fo tuo thgiR
.smra reh daerps dna kcab denael tar ehT
noitom eht gnitaeper ,drawrof depmuh neht dna kcab dellup biF .kcans thgindim reh saw sihT .gnikips etiteppa ,deggeb ehs Ó,eroMÒ .wonk tÕndid ehS .htob saw ti ebyam
.ria eht hguorht gnilriws dna gniddehS
Ó.siht ekil tÕnow sessob ehTÒ
,deleviws srae sÕwodaeM
,niaga ecap ot nageb wodaeM
,niar yna naht rettew
Ó.oot ,gninraw mrotsrednuht ereves a dnA
É tcejbo ot detnaw ,worb reh gniworruf ,wodaeM
.dedda biF Ó,sevac dnAÒ
.smra sih ni efas gnileef
.sniw syawla erutaN
Ó.niaga enohp ym kcehc dluohs I ebyam É ebyaMÒ
.derumrum biF Ó?deb ot kcab emoCÒ
Ó!yeHÒ ÓÑdna ,emit ni pleh dnes ot elba eb tÕnow seitirohtua eht os ,sirbed htiw dekcolb eb lliw sdaor eht dna ,krad-hctip sÕti dna
,moordeb denekrad reh ni htrof dna kcab decap wodaeM
,detrats biF Ó,sraE
É gnivah neeb evÕI smaerd eht ekil tsuJ
Ó,dednettanu eseht evael tÕnaCÒ Ó!hAÒ .dehcra wodaeM
,noitaicossa rieht hguorht ,wodaeM
.enituor gninrom reh gnitrats ,dennapdaed wodaeM Ó,sknahTÒ
.dias biF Ó,ti fo ynAÒ  Ó?trap hcihWÒ
,reh edisni gnidliub noitarepsed a tlef wodaeM .no mih gnigru
Ó.segnahc efil sÕtiÒ
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,deb otni delwarc neht esuom tsevrah elam ehT
Ó.oot ,uoy evol IÒ .liat ,sgel ,smrA
,trapa gnikcams spiL
.sriaper citemsoc otni knis ot hguone egral tÕnsaw
Ó.oot ,sgniht fo diarfa mÕI
,delwocs neht dna demriuqs tar eht
,sserud rednu ,esuoh ehT
.ffo gnivom saw rednuht ehT
.revol reh otni denael ehs sa ti hctulc ot tseb reh did
.55:7 ta ni gniretlif trats dÕyehT
.esuom nekops-tfos dna yhs lacipytoerets a tÕnsaw biF .gnitfil nihc
,nwot morf raf os erÕeWÒ
.spam rehtaew eht dekcehc-elbuod dna dehserfer ylevissesbo
Ó,tihs dna egnahc tneserper smaerd ni smrotSÒ .tniop a sah ehS
.ebyaM .emarf deb eht eb dluoC
.elppin evitisnes a no gnilkcus
,did ehs tahw semit lareves edam ohw ,biF
,htamretfa eht nI
?won ,retsaf neve dniw eht saW
.daeh sÕdneirfyob reh fo kcab eht ot gniog swap knip reh ,denihw wodaeM
.esuac eht osla saw mih htiw gnieb
ÑdnA .moor gnivil eht ni eno dnA ?hcrop eht ni gniliec eht ni tops taht sÕerehT .niaga kael ot trats tÕnseod foor eht epoh I
.ti ni erugif ywodahs eht dnA
.reh rof tnemraedne fo mret sih gnisu
.wolgretfa derahs ni gniksab
esuoM .T dleiF yb
Ó É suovren dna erucesni os gnieb roFÒ
Ó,euqinhcet tneicna yrev A
É eb annog sÕgnihtyrevEÒ
!MOOB-AB ÑeerhT ,ippississiM-owT ,ippississiM-enO
,ylper tÕndid ehs nehW
,sih ot gnirednerrus spiL
,yrgnuh tÕnsaw ehS
Ó.nuf evaH .wolf eht htiw oG
eciffo latned a ta tsinoitpecer a sa gnikrow edam ehs yralas eht tuB
,ecnanimod fo tca reilrae sih ta nwohs dÕehs llirht deretsulf eht gnillaceR
Ó.oot ,taht ekil yehT .noitats yrtnuoc eht no ti tup syawla nac uoY
Ó,neht ,llew ytterp krow tsuMÒ
,hguone eruS .denetsil wodaeM
.spil reh derutpac biF
.mir-rae na gniteem eugnot
.reh naht regnuoy sraey xis saw eH
.retupmoc reh ta detaes saw arteP
.detrevortxe saw eh ,oN
,arteP gnibbob-daeh a denraw dna
.yracs elttil a sÕtI
.esuom rehto eht deretne yllanif
Ó?gninrom siht tsacerof ym hctaw uoy
Ó.llafthgin retfa smrots yvaeh emos teg dÕew dias IÒ .did syawla ehS
Ó.dekcoldnal erÕeWÒ
Ó?ti tuoba hcum os wonk uoy nehw suovren os gnieBÒ Ó?yhWÒ
.delims dna deffins wodaeM
,etaciled dna niht saw hself ehT .eno tfel ehT
,enin-ytnewt ylnO
.thgirb saw nus eht dna ,raelc erew seiks ehT
naem I ... tsimrofnoc ot kcab ti egnahc llÕIÒ
.dehctiwt sreksihw sÕwodaeM
.hsalf a saw ereht ,kcurts msagro reh nehW
,dias yllanif ohw biF saw tI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,haeYÒ Ó?thgirla uoYÒ
,uoy tnaw-w IÒ Ó?taht saw tahWÒ
.seinoob detaroprocninu eht ni tuo
,ria lartnec eht no denrut
.gniwerb mrots a htiW
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,yltfos deksa biF
É eikooc a esuom a evig uoy fI .wonk tÕnod I
Ó.ay evol I esuac ylnOÒ
Ó,erutan fo ecrof lahtel a ton si biFÒ Ó.esuoh eht erÕuoY
.sniol reh ot deltsen erew
!trela rehtaew
.ti timda ot flesreh gnirb tÕndluoc ehs tuB
yllaer ,seramthgin ekil eromÑ
.smra reh dessorc ehS .nwod gnittis dna riahc reh ot gniklaw ,deugra wodaeM
.dah ehs gnihtyreve htiw mih gnigguh
esrup reh nwod tup esuom tsevrah eht ,aera noitpecer eht dniheb gniklaW
.00:8 ta nageb stnemtnioppA
.steehs eht fo elddim eht ot flesreh gnitoocs erofeb wodniw eht ta decnalg yldeirrow ehS
.rethgit reh gnigguh ,dezisahpme-er biF
,tuo gnitrulb erofeb ylsuonimo desuap ehS
swap sih ni stsirw reh gniruces ,dias biF
.reh dnuora smra sih depparw eH
É swodniw wen ekiL
.smaerd eht tuoba mih dlot tÕndah ehS Ó É tuBÒ
.rettulf evissimbus a tlef wodaeM
Õ.sfi-tahwÔ eht htiw ecaep ta eb ot nrael ot dah wodaeM
,lleWÒ .ylnrobbuts dias ehs Ó,oNÒ Ó?yfmoCÒ
Õ?erofeb mlac ehtÔ yb naem yeht tahw siht sI
,nihc reh tsniaga derepsihw eh dna ,sreh ot kcab yaw sti dnuof elzzum siH
04:7 ta eciffo eht otni gniklaw
,esuom tsevrah nedlog
Ó.no emoC ?rehtaew gnikcuf eht tuoba smaerd gnivah erÕuoy dna
,sgel reh neewteb nwo sih dekans biF
.enif eb annog sÕgnihtyrevEÒ
Ó?mM ?gniht taht gniod uoy yhw nehTÒ
.revohsup a eb tÕndluoc uoy
,sreh tem seye eulb siH Ó.nwod wolSÒ
.guh a rof etarepsed ,mih rof pu dehcaer ehS
.oot ,erofeb naht gnikaerc erom raeh dluoc ehS
Ó,em kcuf É ot uoy tnaw IÒ
.sgniht no nips evitisop a gnittup syawla saw eH
.elggig a htiw dias biF
Ó?hguone doog erÕuoy kniht tÕnod uoy ebyaM
.meht nopu ylluf saw mrots ehT
,elbidua ylerab saw tI
.retsaf taeb tI .tÕndid traeh reh hguoht
?evah tar eht did srentrap ynam woH
.ruf-kcab sih ni delruc sregnif reH
.emit eht lla yrrow uoy dnA
,dias tar eht ,neercs eht morf yawa gnikool tuohtiW
.ecivda evig ot devol ,rekrow-oc dna dneirf tseb reh
,sselpleh ,emoc ot ti rof esuoh reh ni tiaw dÕehs dnA
Ó.noitcartsid elttil a siÒ
.luos dna ,dnim ,ydoB
.nid tneserpinmo ,ydaets a saw niar eht
,aera noitpecer eht ot denruter wodaeM nehW
Ó.ssenlooc fo snoisuled htiw dren regae-revo na sÕeh ,haNÒ
.gniremmah a draeh wodaeM
.deddon wodaeM Ó.hcuot yM
.yawa tpews eb dluoc taht gniht level-ecafrus emos tÕnsaw sraef reh fo esuac toor ehT
,dias biF Ó,deen uoy tahW
.noitnetta dehsiler ohw retteg-og tnedifnoc A
spih sih deimmihs biF
.kniht ot redrah emaceb tI
,tuo deirc dna depsag wodaeM
.dlrow edistuo on saw erehT
.od uoy sa hcum sa yrrow tÕnseod stnemtimmoc rieht ni eruces enoemos esuaceBÒ
.gniliec eht no swodahs eht ta gnirats
,ylbaredisnoc pu dekcip dniw lirpA eht ,edistuO
ylper ot detrats biF
.deretaw seye sÕwodaeM
.lenparhs ekil erof eht ot gnulf neeb evÕtsum snoitome reh
.hctaw odanrot a sÕereht É sÕerehTÒ
.decnuob sserttam ehT
.demuser biF Ó?detcartsid dna doog uoy teg ot ,woNÒ .dehgis wodaeM
.yaw deirruh ,gniffuh a nI
,deppots ehS Ó?wodaeMÒ
.ecneirepxe eht tuoba saw tI
,efas siht eb ot biF htiw pihsnoitaler ruoy tnaw uoY
Ó.uoy tuohtiw gniviLÒ
.derepmihw wodaeM Ó?tahw od oTÒ Ó.oot
.dehcleuqs slatineg riehT !noitcirf eht
Ó?ytic eht ni
,xal gniog erofeb gnitlih ,biF
,tlep reh tub gnihton gniraew
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil erÕuoY
Ó.ti rof ksAÒ ,dehtaerb eh
.sraet eht kcab dloh tÕndluoc ehS Ó É yeHÒ
.noitacol larur reh nopu tsomla
É erom tib a dnA .erom tib a nehT
.yltoh gnihsulb skeehc reh tlef ehS
.elbbur ni evila deirub teg ylbaborp dÕeWÒ
.hgiht reh tsniaga dekop noitcere siH Ó.uoy tnaw IÒ
,derussa tar nworb eht Ó,yrrow tÕnoDÒ
É eittoh a sÕeh sseug I tuBÒ Ó!yeHÒ
,repsihw elbarenluv a htiw ,deksa wodaeM
.etunim tsal syawlA
,srae reh sa evitisnes sa tÕnsaw tI
,naem I .lanoitar syawla tÕnera sraeFÒ
Ó.suolucidir sÕtahTÒ Ó.trats oTÒ
.skeehc reh ta gnibbur
.yltoh derevihs wodaeM
,moob suorednuht a htiW .pu til moor ehT
.esuap enoyna ekam dluow ereht nwod gniog dna htaed neewteb gnisoohC .ecapslwarc ypeerc-repus taht tsuJ
.ereh teg yeht nehw pu kcab ti nrut uoy ekam annog tsuj erÕyehTÒ
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
Ó.emit eht llAÒ .delffins wodaeM
Ó?ton mÕI kniht uoy sekam tahWÒ
.derepsihw wodaeM Ó,wonk IÒ
!ti tuoba nettogrof tsomla dÕehS
Ó.suoicsnocbus ruoy ot stneserper eh tahw tuoba si siht ,yawynAÒ
,dias wodaeM ,flesreh gnitcelloC Ó.retteb hcuMÒ .won
,tar ehT .arteP dlot dÕehS
.ti ees tÕndluoc wodaeM hguoht
.stbuod dna raef laitnetsixe reh rof mlab a saw biF
Ó.taht kniht reven dluow I
,hguone gniraeh ,biF
,yawa llaf dluow sllaw ehT .epacse ot elbanu
.traeh reh evoba eno eht
.rednuht tÕnsaw ti ,emit siht ,tuB
.ydob reh dehcra wodaeM
.reh edisni deppils neht dna
Ó.thginot mrots ot desoppuSÒ
Ó É peels ot elba eb tÕnow I .deriw oot mÕIÒ
.ssik a rof ni detlit ehs
!won ,noosnom a yllacitcarp saw niar ehT
É tub ,lufrednow sleef tI
Ó?yad lla em gnizicitirc eb ot gniog uoy erAÒ
.noitaxaler fo dohtem foorp-liaf a si sihT .yrrow tÕnod
Ó.lla retfa ,mrots eht hguorht ti edam ekil skooLÒ
,sÕwodaeM ta dnekeew eht gnidneps saw eH
,sevael gnuoy htiw hserf ,seert ehT
Ó É yrros-s mÕIÒ Ó É wodaeMÒ
.reh dnuora yllacitoahc gnilriws dlrow eht
.dehsulf dna yzah reh gnivael
efil elttil ,lanoitidart ruoy ot ni gnimoc sÕeHÒ
.egde eht no tas ,pmal eht yb enohp reh gnittup ,wodaeM
É I dna ,redlo mÕI dna ,lrig yrtnuoc roop a tsuj mÕI wonk IÒ
.reh dniheb pu denoops eh ,edisa gnilggirW
.xes reh morf werdhtiw liat sih
.daeh reh evoba smra reh gninnip dna
sgel reh daerps wodaeM
,derewsna tÕndah llits ehs gnizilaer
.taorhttuc ytterp teg dluoc sboj aideM
.mhtyhr nekorbnu na otni delttes eh litnu
.ruf sih ni gnilruc sregnif
?taebtraeh ym taht sI
.ffuh a htiw dias yllanif wodaeM
,emit emas eht ta ,tuB
.mih htiw tnew dna dekaeuqs wodaeM
.nwod kcab reh nip ot thgiew sih desu biF
gnitfird erofeb sirotilc reh gnizarg yllufesoprup
.swodniw eht lla no sdnilb eht denepo dna
,ysae dehtaerb wodaeM
,debborht srae reh ,nooS
.sdileye reh hguorht neve elbisiv
.nihc reh no delbbin eH Ó É tsuj-j I É IÒ
.dias biF lla saw Ó,em no sucoFÒ
moc.yrrufos.lerriuqs ta
.did yllaer ehS .ot deirt ehS
.elpmis saw noitulos eht dna ,thgir saw arteP ebyaM
,ecnavda dna evivrus oT
.su tsuJ  .siht tsuJ
.thgir ylbaborp saw arteP wenk ehS
Ó,uoy esol ot tnaw tÕnod IÒ
.noitom sÕwodaeM gnikcimim ,tnew arteP
.did syawla ehs ekil meht morf edih ot deirT
.deksa biF Ó?doog uoYÒ
.nwod kcab meht hsup
.tnemom a rof deldduc ecim owt ehT
.yltneitap dias eh
.sserttam eht pota yal ot reh rof gnirutseg
.nosinu ytaorht ni dekaeuqs ecim ehT
.enoyna htiw evol ni ylpeed siht neeb reven evÕI
.pu gninrub saw gnihtyrevE
,ekorb ssik eht nehW
.pu kcab tis ot gniyrt ,dediced wodaeM
,tsul htiw dedaehthgiL
Ó É semoc odanrot eht erofeb ereht teg ew os ti emit attog eWÒ
,elddim-tnorf eht nwod etihw ymaerc
.gnimoc saw mrots A
.gnissapmocne-lla saw erusaelp ehT
.deffocs tar ehT Ó?woH ?tahWÒ
Ó.dettimmoc ton mÕI naem tÕnseod ylop mÕI esuac tsuj ,yeHÒ
.dehctiwt sreksihw siH
.rehtegot ni evom dÕyeht nehw gniksa syawla saw arteP
.wodaeM drawot riahc reh gnileviws
,ni enohp nwo reh tup ot sehtolc on gnivah ,wodaeM
,meht egdod ot deirt ehS
.detarbiv enohp sÕwodaeM
,sretupmoc gnipeels eht pu ekow esuom tsevrah ehT
.ti fo tuo dekool dna wodniw eht ot derednaw ylfeirb wodaeM Ó.wonk IÒ
.won ,reh gnittur saw eH
Ó,klat ot eno yllaer erÕuoYÒ
.gnihtyna deniur tÕnevah uoYÒ
.ecaf reh gnilzzun ,deksa biF Ó?tahw roFÒ
.esu ot srotcod dna stsineigyh eht rof ydaer eb dÕyeht os tnempiuqe dna sthgil eht no denrut dna
?deussi tsuj ebyaM ?wonk uoY .gninraw odanrot a eb dluoc erehTÒ
.derumrum biF Ó,ti yas nac uoYÒ
.demsaps xes reh sa gnisluvnoc ydob
.neppah efil tel ot daH
,tnettimretni koot hteetkcub siH .htooms dna toh
Ó.lennuf eht otni pu dekcus teg tÕnod ew fI
.reh ta kcab gnitniuqs
,esuoM .T dleiF yb
.deb eht ot kcab reh gniggut ydaerla saw eH
.gniniartS .gninaorG
,liat elisneherp reh htiw deyalp eh elihW
.thginot reh detiawa smaerd retteb wenk ehs
,ylluf pu tas dna niaga denway biF
.yletanoissap ,reh dessik biF
.dias tar eht Ó,emit eht fo tser eht ffo-nrut eguh a sÕti tuB .haeY
,gnidda erofeb sciryl eht fo emos gnihtuom
Ó?gniod uoy era tahWÒ
,yletamitni dehtaerb biF Ó,tcefrep erÕuoY
.lla retfa ,seikooc esoht dah evÕdluohs ylbaborp I
.gninthgil eht yb detteuohlis saw erugif sÕbiF  !HSALF
.noitats VT silopanaidnI na rof namrehtaew yadkeew gninrom eht saw eH .dias biF
?I ma ,laudividni evitagen a ton mÕI
.tluafed eciffo eht ot ti gnignahc
.esle erehwyreve dlog hcir
,delbmum wodaeM Ó?lla taht sIÒ
?uoy tpurroc ot gnitnaw fo smret ni ,lleWÒ
.ydob sih dnuora meht depparw dna
,ssa yrruf sih deporg swap reH
.dehsurb sreksihw yesuom riehT Ó.mmh-mMÒ .deksa ehs Ó?od IÒ
.dlrow ruoy egnarraer nac ti woH
,deksa ,biF ,dneirfyob reh
?sgniht egnahc taht dluow woH .deirram teg rO
,sreh ot eson yffins ,knip sih gnihcuot
.dias dah tsacerof eht ekil tsuJ .eno gib A
?reippah em ekam ti dluoW
Ó É diputs mÕI kniht tsum uoYÒ
gnivah neeb dÕehs smaerd ehT
.raef eht ekahs ot elbanu ,deksa wodaeM Ó?wonk uoy od woHÒ
,nwod peed saw tI
tÕndiDÒ  .eciwt ro ecno tsacswen sih no neeb neve dah
,siht gniod saw eh elihW
Ó,wonk ot boj ym sÕtIÒ
,rehto eht rof eno dedart biF
?yrc ot tnaw I ekil leef I od yhw É oS
.kcuts gnitteg erew sdrow reH Ó É tÕnac I tub
.dees sih htiw reh dellif dna deslup eh sa keehc reh tsniaga denaom
.noitseuq eht yb desirprus
,peels ot kcab gnitfirD .denway wodaeM
.noitats VT sih morf ruoh-flah a
.reh evoba sruof ot gnivom
gnippar cimhtyhr ,duol eht ot MA
.egassap reh otni yaw rieht gnilruc dna
.tup yats ot dediced ehs ,yletamitlU
,noisolpxe citcamilc eht nI Ó É taerg saw taht É ti
.swodniw eht delttar rednuht tnatsiD
ÓnoitcartsiD elttiL AÒ:yojne esaelP
.yawyna reh ot tog ti tub
.saw ti wenk ehs ,ecneirepxe morf ,tuB
.esimorp a ekil thgil eht erow
.nwod rehtruf emulov oidar eht nrut ot gnihcaer
,ecalp sti koot sregnif siH
.esab eht ta ti deppirg eH
tuhs seye reh dezeeuqs ehS
.mmH ?pleh taht dluoW ?seikooC
.mih htaeneb derepmihw wodaeM
Ó.yaw taht ti peek ot si ti redrah eht ,rehtegot erÕuoy regnol eht tuB .gniht denifednu
Ó,senob ym ni taht tlef IÒ !MOOB
.deppots dah niar eht
Ó.flesti efil sa dlo sAÒ
.ti no gnilkcus thgirtuo neht dna gnissik
:sÕwodaeM ekil yltcaxe denrettap saw ruf siH
,detaeper eh Ó,xaleRÒ Ó É yako-o É hOÒ
Ó.rettoh em edam Õdoog-ydoogÔ a gnieb dias uoy thguoht IÒ .desucca arteP
era É Ò É sreh tsniaga elzzum sih gnilzzun
.ebol suonegore na fo egde eht dnuora dekcil biF Ó.enif É tsuj
.dlo saw esuoh ehT
,eno sa desuf ,erew yeht sa esolc sA ?sih rO
.nehw kcab yaw stnerapdnarg sÕwodaeM yb tliuB
,enil suoivbo ,yseehc a hcus saw tI
Ó.neppah annog ton sÕtahTÒ .eltneg eciov
Ó,ot deen tÕnod uoY !ha-
.gnitsujda slipup ,wap a htiw
Ó,nam eht ot ti gnikcits ta doog yrev ton erÕuoYÒ
Ó?retaw peed É ekil tÕnod IÒ
Ó.kool yllaer dluohs I
,spil sih ot pit gnilggiw eht thguorb eH
Ó?Õecrof edistuo na yb nopu detca litnu tser ta yats tser ta
,deksa biF Ó?naem uoy od tahWÒ
Ó.xaler tsuJÒ .sreh ot keehc sih debbur dna sedis reh degassam biF Ó!kcab ti ekat IÒ