.enots eht fo tuo devrac moor dezis yletaredom a ot neht dna
.og mih tel dluow yeht ebyam
mih fo daeha draug eht ees ot pu dekool dnumgiS dna
,edis rehtie no tas sllub fo
kcab sih dehsup dna
,emit emos etiuq rof dnim s’dnumgiS no neeb dah draug regnuoy ehT
:ratla eht fo edis etisoppo eht no yal
,spurrits eht morf pils ot stoob sih gnicrof ,detlob deets siH
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
.dias redael tidnab eht
.hcrot a gnidloh meht fo eno
.eelf dluoc eh erofeb rehto eht debbarg dna
”,won ssenisub ynnuf oN“
dael eht koot yltneidebo eh os
,erusaert on si ereht fI
.evom ot deirt eh nehw hself sih otni gud
dnuora denrut eh erofeb
.hteet sih tirg mih gnikam
.nwo rieht fo esroh a no hcae ,edis a ot owt
.noitcesretni eht dedraug yeht sa
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
.stiurcer hserf neeb ylno dah sdraug daed eerht eht fo owT
***  .ssenkcalb fo aes a otni tsurht saw dna
;oga gnol noitisop s’reciffo na dereffo neeb evah dluow eh
hteet sih dettirg dnumgiS
”,rewsna ruoy si noitanitsed ruO“
.stsirw s’dnumgiS deruces taht
decamirg dnumgiS
.wolb gnillik s’retsnom eht rof noitaraperp ni tuhs seye sih dewercs dna
mih edam rehtaf a tuohtiw nrob gnieb ,revewoh
.mih gnisahc tsaeb denroh eht htiw pots t’ndluoc eh tub
dnuos gnippals ehT .thgir tnew eh
.esac eht ylraen yrev saw hcihw
,thgir sih ot dekool eH
tsaeb eht fo staebfooh ehT
noitseuq ni ”syob“ eht fo eno sa deplug dnumgiS
”.esaelp ,og em tel woN“ .dias eh
,noitcesretni yaw-ruof a tA
daeh sti morf gnidurtorp snroh eht was dnumgiS tub
.devirra reven etubirt eht taht
ecin neeb evah dluow tI
.niks sih tsniaga ylthgils esaercni
,enod llew boj a rof mih etulas dluow
”?gniod uoy era tahW“
.fo kaeps ot romra lautca yna dah meht fo wef yreV
seisatnaf dwel ot nrut dluow sthguoht siH
wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.epacse sih ekam dluoc eh os
.etsat dluow tsaef eht suoiciled
edisni morf ria pmad ,looc ehT
,tibbar daed a ekil dellems llits ylbaborp niks siH .tiaw ot
esae htiw kcen s’tidnab eno deppans ti sa
.trac eht gnivird nam ylredle eht ta
,hguor ,egral a nehw
.ylhsrah dehgual lanimirc ehT  ”?og ot eerf I ma-
teef erab sih otno drawpu mih deknay
deppots tub lla dah sevooh gnippolc ehT .gniog peek dna
-erofeb ereh neeb dah dnumgiS
,lla retfa ,tae ot dah stidnab nevE
,yam ti sa taht eB
.elpmet eht fo ssenkcalb eht drawot
mih deppals dah ohw tidnab ehT
klof suoigiler dna stnahcrem yb desu daor trid a
.elpmet eht ni repeed morf gniohce
,meht wonk t’ndid dnumgiS
sreizarb enots owt yb deknalf
epor esraoc eht dna
”.nihtiw serusaert erom ynam era ereht tub
.esroh eht morf llef eh sa
,sraey neetruof ylraen rof tums cihpromoporhtna
.ecnartne elpmet eht ta devirra yeht erofeb sruoh lareves saw tI  ***  .stoidI
.yllaer elpmet a ,ereh morf selim lareves evac a si erehT
,derethguals neeb dah ygrelc suoigiler ehT
.erusaert eht laets ew elihw su rof tiab emos eb ot gniog er’uoy oS
.sgel dna smra sih ot doof eht gnidloh epor eht eitnu ot detrats eh erofeb
.eerced layor a ot gnidrocca ”pihsredael fo noitisop a rof tifnu“
stidnab eht tcartsid ot ti dedeen eH
,hguone erus dna mih dniheb decnalg eH
.noitomorp a ni detseretni tib tsael eht t’nsaw dnumgiS
tuoba thguoht eH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
egamirglip eht fo ytitcnas eht ,yloh revewoH
”.od uoy fi uoy llik ot ereh gnitiaw eb lliw syob ym fo owt esuaceb kcab gninrut fo kniht t’nod dnA
ssenkcalb eht morf detfird seirc gnilgrug erom lareves erofeb tnemom feirb a rof dewollof
,lairub reporp a snoinapmoc gnilevart sih evig dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
,tsrow eht gnitcepxe
,nepo deppir saw trac dnoces eht ni lrig gnuoy eht fo ebor eht
.resolc gnitteg ylwols erew
.drawrof noitnetta sih gninrut erofeb
,drawrof llef eh dna
.mih ta delims dna denrut
roolf enots eht fo eceip nekorb a no thguac toof s’dnumgiS  .tnemom eht yb reduol gnitteg erew yeht hguoht
flesmih dnuof dna
sniol sih ni noisnet eht eveiler ot elba neeb dah eh ecnis gnol oot neeb dah tI
.gnidraug neeb dah eh trac eht fo sleehw eht fo eno tsniaga pu gninael saw dna
.daeh s’revird navarac eht ni flesti deirub dna
.ssenkrad eht ni dekrul revetahw ro
.elpmet siht ot su dael ot gniog era uoY .ton yletulosbA
.tif was ti revenehw mialc ot tsaeb eht rof tfel dna
.ediced ot ecnahc a teg t’ndid yehT
strac eht tuoba nwerts yal taht seidob eht ta
”.sredluohs ruoy morf daeh ruoy gnitarapes ni erusaelp taerg yrev ekat dluow syob ym fo eno erus m’I ,t’nod uoy fI
,deilper dnumgiS ”,kcul daB“
,doolb ward ot hguone t’nsaw ti elihW
.flesmih ot derepsihw dnumgiS
.snekcihc dna stibbar sa hcus slamina emag llams fo sessacrac desserd dna denniks eht osla erew ereht tub ,selbategev dna
.llaw tfel eht no dnah eno gnipeek
,tiurf yltsom ,doof deirrac
,tsehc sih nwod drows nwo s’dnumgiS fo edalb eht deggard yltneg
.daor eht nwod ylsuorednop devom navarac eht sa no deggard sruoh ehT
,nur ot deirt eh fi spets owt koot eh erofeb daed eb dluow eh taht wenk dnumgiS
]…ffuts dna sgniht erehw regnahffilc a no dedne ew dna ,ecalp koot stneve dna sretcarahc[ ,emit tsaL ]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[   .yrruF oS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
revird eht ediseb namow gnuoy ehT
.eerf kaerb ot gniyrt saw ti fi sa
,ssaP radlaK evoba gnuh sduolc htiw dettod yks thgirb A  2 fo
.daor eht nwod mih dehsup dna
-yawyna redael eht saw eh demussa eh
dluoc dnumgiS .noitartsurf dna
.tiab ,yaw taht gniog peeK“
daeh sih gnihcaorppa yltfiws
,eulb tnaillirb saw rehto eht elihw
”etubirT s’ruatoniM A“
,namow gnuoy a tas mih ot txeN
,thgit ylbatrofmocnu emaceb stnap sih fo hctorc eht sa esroh sih no flesmih detsujda eH
.ynapmoc eht ni sreidlostoof tsedlo eht fo eno mih edam ytrof ylraen gnieb dna
”etubirT s’ruatoniM A“   :yojne esaelP
liam s’dnumgiS gniraew saw
.strap eseht morf eb ton tsum uoY“
.rekciltoob ,ecneitap ym yrt t’noD“
derehtag dah meht fo emoS
,draug hcus eno ,dnumgiS
nosaer doog eno em eviG
.evom ot dah eh fi mih tsniaga gnippolf tiab eht evah t’ndluow eh tsael ta tub
ot derad eh sa tsaf sa nar dna denrut eh
.thgiarts gniog rehto eht dna
.mih dnuora ssenkcalb ykni eht otni retsaf nur ot flesmih dehsup dnumgiS dna
,denot s’draug regnuoy eht fo
,egailof eht morf tsrub sdnagirb fo puorg a ees ot emit ni
.ned nwo sti ni retsnom eht revuenamtuo ot elba eb dluow eh ebyaM
.edalb reh werd ehs sa dnuos eht ecaf ot esroh reh nrut
,htarw s’redael rieht fo diarfa erom erew yeht rehtehw ediced ot gniyrt fi sa teef rieht no gnitfihs erew sdnagirb owt eht dna
gnivird erew yeht strac ehT
.lla ta reidlos a eb ot ykcul saw dnumgiS ,sthgir lla yB
.tcaer ot tidnab rehtie rof tsaf oot ,noitcesretni eht otni degrahc tsaeb defooh
,tsehc sih ni decar traeh s’dnumgiS
.hcruhc eht fo srebmem htiw ezinretarf netfo ton did sdraug eht sa
,depahs-nam ,evissam A
.demuser ecnelis neht dna
.sgel dna smra s’dnumgiS ot doof eht gniyt nageb eh sa
.lio detnecs htiw dellif snisab eznorb dna
.elpmet eht fo shtped eht otni deunitnoc dna
,kcab sih dniheb deit erew stsirw siH
,dias dah dnumgiS sA
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,sgnireffo eseht reviled ot yaw ruo no erew eW
.trela niamer ot tluciffid gnivorp saw ti dna
.kcen sih ta drows nwo s’draug eht gnitniop dna
,navarac eht deknalf sdraug ruoF
,drawrof degdurt eh sa
.eciohc rehto on dah eH
thgil eht fo egnar fo tuo saw eh taht niatrec saw eh litnu
.htrof dna kcab decap
,yad a flah tsuj ni detelpmoc neeb evah dluoc pirt dnuor ehT
.dekrab redael ehT
.tneve eht rof sebor suoigiler etihw ni dalc htob erew yeht dna
.lanimirc lanif eht fo emaceb tahw hctaw ot dnuora kcits t’ndid dnumgiS
sllah eht hguorht deohce enots eht tsniaga teef erab sih fo
.stnap sih fo dnabtsiaw eht evoba tsuj
.won retsnom eht dnuora teg ot gniog saw dnumgiS yaw on saw erehT
.strac eht fo tnorf eht drawot mih dehsup dna
etal ydaerla erew yeht
.deeps gninethgirf htiw navarac eht no nwod gniraeb
yawyna dnats ot deirt eh tub ,gnuts seot siH
.evila esroh elgnis a tfel t’ndah yeht
niks s’dnumgiS morf drows eht detfil eh sa
ti htiw dedilloc eh erofeb
.htap desu-llew eht nwod
.efil s’dnumgiS htrow t’nsaw
hself erab sih gnissik ,drawtuo detfird
.gnileer sesnes sih tnes dna
yllautca dah yeht taht
”!won luah laer eht teg ot gniog er’ew ,stneg ,thgirlA“
.daeh sih koohs dna
.tnew yeht evac eht otni rehtruf eht relooc emaceb ylno ti dna
”.erac I lla rof kool ew elihw uoy llik nac ereht ni sevil revetahw neht
stidnab eht sa sega ekil
emit txen ni enuT
staebfooh gnippolc ,tnatsiD
.ekawa deppals saw dnumgiS
.enivob hcae fo sedis eht revo xaw deppird dah taht
.spil sih ot hcuop retaw rehtael sih detfil eh sa
”?tuoba gniklat uoy era tahW
,morf emoc dah sdnuos eht erehw llet ot elbissopmi saw tI
trac eht fo renroc nedoow eht retsiger ot emit dah ylerab seye s’dnumgiS
-ytud eht rof wor a ni sraey eerht tsap eht nesohc neeb evah ot hguone ”ykcul“
degnevacs ekil dekool tahw ni dehtolc yllacipyt dna
,emit siht taht wenk dnumgiS
.esruoc fo ,ti ssentiw ot deyats reven smirglip ehT
,yag gnitirw neeb sah ohw ,godknitS yb
nwo sih tsniaga desserp ydob yriah
ecnatsid eht ni spets-fooh yvaeh eht dna
”.raey fo emit siht gniog neeb evah dluoc ew ecalp eno ylno si erehT“ .dias eh
nruter ot evah dluow eh
yrlewej fo lufdnah a si raf os ti rof wohs ot tog ev’ew lla dnA“
toof dednuow sih no drawrof delbboh
ratla eht dessap puorg ehT
-eglub gnibborht sih tsniaga gnidnirg skeehc ssa dnuor s’leinahtaN fo kniht tub pleh t’ndluoc eh ,llitS
,detsujda seye sih erofeb llaw enots a otni tsrif-ecaf nur t’ndluow eh depoh dnumgiS
woh dna nruter rieht nopu eb dluow modgnik eht yppah woh
.epoh fo remmilg A
,sraey net tsomla rof
,gnuoy ylriaf yllautca erew stidnab rehto neves eht taht deciton dnumgiS
navarac eht draug ot ronoh taerg a sa nees saw tI
dias eh ”,rewsna dooG“
”.won thgir nepo ylleb ruoy tuc t’ndluohs I yhw
dnumgiS dniheb enil ni llef redael ehT
nruter ni don etilop a reh evag dnumgiS
.os gniod morf mih gnitneverp gniht rehtona tsuj saw ytud egamirglip siht dna
.etuor rehto siht ekat ll’eW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
egacbir sih tsniaga gnidnuop
.ybraen saw leinahtaN nehw etartnecnoc ot tluciffid ti dnuof netfo eh dna
tniop drows eht fo erusserp eht tlef eh nehw hteet sih gnittirg
,maercs tsrif eht draeh eh nehT
.mih dniheb morf emoc t’ndluow tsaeb eht taht saw epoh ylno siH
.mih dniheb elggag deretsulc a ni dehcram sdnagirb eht sa
.tsael ta rof lufknaht saw dnumgiS taht gnihtemos
seutats enots owT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,romra sih fo deppirts neeb dah eH
,daor eht morf ecnatsid trohs a
,yrujni roirp a morf ylbaborp ,yssalg dna yerg saw seye sih fo enO
.ssendnilb fo stnemom wef a retfa thgil mid eht ot detsujda seye sih ,ylikcuL
,dlog ni deppit erew snroh ehT
gnik eht nraw sa llew sa
syawedis denrut dlrow eht dna
sdnagirb owt eht dehctaw dna
,rettam taht rof sehtolc sih fo tsom dna
ybraen strac eht hguorht gnitoor erew sdnagirb rehto eht llet
.ti fo erutcip etarucca na rebmemer ot yltfiws oot delf dah yeht dna
demees tahw rof ereht detiaw eH
,nrevac eht fo sllaw enots dna roolf trid eht etanimulli ot sehcrot til dah meht dniheb stidnab owT
.pal sih revo lla stug s’dnumgiS llips ot troffe hcum nekat evah t’ndluow ti
taorht sih otni pu depael traeh s’dnumgiS
detatcid erutpircs tub
epor eht tuc redael tidnab ehT
.ffo meht yrp ot yrt ot revo dehsur stidnab eht fo emos dna
.htap tfel eht nwod nar eh sa
,mih ta nwod deralg dnagirb ehT
.sevac ni evil stsaeb fo rennam llA“ .dias eh
,secnatsmucric lamron rednU
.thgin fo daed eht litnu knird lla dluow yeht dna
,ecnegilletni sih tuoba gnitsaob s’redael eht lla rof tub
,thgilhcrot eht ni detteuohlis saw tI
”etubirT s’ruatoniM A“
.noitcesretni yaw-ruof rehtona ta
flesmih ot delbmurg dnumgiS  ”.erac t’nod I
.llud dna suoidet ssel yna boj eht ekam t’ndid
sdoow eht sdrawot dekool eH
ecaf s’dnumgiS tsap welf worra nA
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”,daed era syob ym fo owT“
,ssenkrad eht hguorht nar eh sA
.meht ot saw kcab sih hguoht neve
drawrof dnumgiS dehsup redael tidnab ehT
,siht devivrus dnumgiS fI
1 traP ,godknitS yb
.dereens lanimirc eht
,nihtiw sehcir eht dna evac eht tuoba stidnab eht dlot eh fI
.deksa dnumgiS ”?gnihtyna ees t’nac I fi gniog peek I nac woH“
,eciohc txen eht ta dna ,tfel denrut eh
kcab sih fo ffo kcaspank eht koot stidnab eht fo redael ehT
,strac nedoow derevoc-savnac owt dellup sesroh nworb owt ,yad siht nO
seldnac suoigiler htiw derevoc
.ssenkrad otni deraeppasid taht yawllah nepo-ediw ,egral a
draug eht fo rebmem a neeb dah eH
ecnartne eht ot noitaler ni saw eh erehw fo kcart tsol yletelpmoc dah eH
neeb dah dnumgiS dna
trac tsrif eht ni neeb dah sehcir elttil tahw
.ecap ylerusiel rieht tpek srevird eht sa esroh sih no yldi tas
moor eht ot tixe rehto ylno ehT
dias eh ”!nmad ,nmad ,nmaD“
hcum a eb egamirglip eht taht
,shtaerw latnemanro htiw denroda saw gninepo eht tub ,evac a saw ti
redluohs sih debbarg dnah ekil-namuh
gnithgif tnatsid fo dnuos ehT
etubirt eht htiw etal os neeb puorg a dah ecno ylnO
.evac eht fo wam kcalb ,gnipag eht drawot devohs saw eh sa
ssenkrad eht ni dehcuorc eH
.lla ta navarac eht ekat ot elba neeb dah yeht nosaer ylno eht ylbaborp saw esirprus fo tnemele ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.elpmet eht ni dekrul yllautca tahw gniredisnoc elfirt erem a saw taerht tidnab ehT
drawrof tperc dnumgiS
flesmih ot yltfos delkcuhc eH
mih fo daeha egassap krad eht nwod doof eht dessot eH
,mih dniheb syaw a etiuq llits erew
.htruof sih eb dluow siht
,tfel eht ot sdoow eht morf detpure esion gnipoohw duol A
spets enots ot yaw evag roolf trid eht ,yllautnevE
thgir eht ot gnidaeh eno
.nevahsnu dna derracs
”,sdrawoc uoy ,eelf ,no emoC“
,serutaef hguor dah ecaf s’nam ehT
”,elpmet ruoy s’erehT“  .ruoh na naht erom yb
.soraT fo modgnik eht ni seitic neewteb levart ot
.xenna lautir eht saw siht
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,godknitS yb
A“  .drabbacs sti ni ti dehtaehs dna
.ruatonim eht htiw retnuocne sih sevivrus dnumgiS fi tuo dnif ot
.rehto hcae dnuora dellor seugnot rieht sa
,noitcesretni eht ta gnitiaw erew stidnab eht fo owt
.mih htiw enola emit emos dneps ot leinahtaN draug wollef sih ecnivnoc ot elba eb dluow eh spahreP
.dnoces eht morf emag dna doof fo lluf skcap rieht deffuts dah srehto dna
saw taht ecap gniklaw a ot dewols won dna
,owt otni tilps egassap devrac
xenna lautir s’elpmet eht otni nekat gnieb erofeb snisab eht ta desselb eb dluow sgnireffo eht ,yllamroN
.nway a delfits dnumgiS
.gnidnal lufniap eht morf ecaf sih dleihs ot gniganam ylerab
dnumgiS .ybraen yrev
,ylleb ygdup sih otni ylmrif
,dlot eb hturt dna ,ti rof mih no nwod dekool reven dah sedarmoc sih
.llaw eht tsniaga ylmrif
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
gnisserp saw ti litnu riah ydob hguor sih hguorht
,talf eht ,elihw a retfA
,sselpot reh gnivael
.hguoht ,raey detsalb yreve egamirglip siht ot dengissa eb ton ot
edirp fo erutxim a saw noisserpxe sih dna
,seye sih denepo yltnatculer dna detnurg eH
.gnihtolc detool dna
.noisufnoc fo ksam a ecaf sih
,levart ot ecnatsid fo tib riaf a llits saw ereht taht wenk eH
delttar romra liam s’dnumgiS  .riaffa regnol
?efil ruoy eulav uoy oD“
?loof a rof em ekat uoy oD“
.edisni mih dehcram redael eht sa
,sesiotrot sa ydaets dna wols
temleh sih fo edis eht kcurts enots a erofeb
.neht drawrof yaw ruoy leeF“
-redael tidnab ehT
drabbacs sih fo tuo yawflah ti knay ot emit dah ylno tub
”ronoh“ desoppus ehT
”,kniht ot mees uoy sa diputs sa ton m’I“
,drows sih fo tlih eht deppirg dnumgiS
.hsif a ekil reh gnittug morf snolef eht deppots t’ndah taht tub
,siad ralucric a no moor eht fo retnec eht ni tas ratla ytpme nA
sreidlos wollef siH
”.doof fo lluf trac a dna
.sessacrac tibbar owt dna selbategev emos tuo dellup dna
.ylthgirb denrub taht
,llems ytsum a dah ria ehT
.htap thgiarts eht otni
eseht piks nac uoy
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.nirg a ni drawpu denrut spil s’dnagirb ehT
,erutaerc eht despmilg
srae sih dehcaer
thgir rehtona edam eh sa
,tnemgduj retteb sih tsniagA