A“  .noisneherppa ni revo dellor hcamots sih dna
moor eht ot tixe rehto ylno ehT
.erusaelp ni gnilworg yllacitcarp
tnecs eht morf nups daeh sih elihw
llaw eht no depmuls eh ,gnitnaP
niks sih otni erutxim labreh eht degassam soroB sa
,yllanogaid worbeye thgir sih tilps senil racs owT
niaga ecno denrub skeehc s’dnumgiS
.edutitta evissergga ylremrof sih ot tsartnoc krats ni
retnec eht ni teprac erauqs
nekciht ot trats kcoc retsnom taht ees dluoc dnumgiS
.elcsum fo gnir gnireviuq eht kcilf dna
smra egral sti otni pu mih depoocs tsaeb eht sa
,thgir eht ot ti detniop dna
ylbidua plug mih edam hself sih tsniaga eson s’erutaerc eht fo hcuot eht fo yromem feirb A
denruter nam-llub eht erofeb gnol t’nsaw tI
retaw eht otni sdnah egral sih fo eno deppid eH
koohs ydob elohw sih sa
spil sih depacse naorg derusaelp A
ylnrets os mih ta gniralg soroB
.esnopser ni detnap dna detnurg soroB sa gnir laidem eht htiw gniyot
.dias ruatonim eht
,dekcus dna dekcus erutaerc ehT
.erusaert dnif ot depoh yeht erehw
”?seveiht eb-dluow dna
.def-llew naht erom nam-llub eht tpek etubirt eht taht desseug dnumgiS
,niaga moor eht tfel soroB
.yaw eht fo tser eht but eht dellif dna
.ssa yfeeb s'soroB deppals stun sih sa gnitnurg
htuom s’dnumgiS edam ti fo thgiew eht dna
.tnemtnioppasid ni derepmihw dnumgiS dna
.xamilc drawot mih gnigru
.etsat elbatceled eht ta denoows dnumgiS dna
mucerp s’ruatonim eht fo pollod A
.denekciht tfahs sih dna
.ot gnitnaw flesmih dnuof dnumgiS ekil
”…demussa I naht nekops-llew erom …er’uoY“
.dehsinruf llew ylgnisirprus saw moor ehT
!neeb dah taht nosaes elbarusaelp a tahW
,retaw eht ni tuo dehcterts dnumgiS
deddon soroB  ”.uoy knaht
,llub a ekil tlef tahw yb nwolb gnieb fo gnileef eht
,sdog hO“ …tnaem taht os
.og ot eerf era uoY“
yfirtcele ylsuoenatlumis ot demees hcuot siH
tuo ekans ot eugnot enivob sih rof
”?etubirt deniur ruoy fo ecalp ni reffo ot uoy evah tahW
.daetsni ruatonim evissam eht yb dellik eb ot tuoba flesmih dnuof tub
.llew sa mih no tceffe na gnivah ylraelc tnecs eht
ssa dna ,spih
,gnileef gnisuora ylddo na saw tI
,esrevrep dna dwel os saw tI  .tsehc yzzuf
,esab eht ot knus eh sa lavorppa ni detnurg soroB
”.emit gnol yrev a ni feiler dah …t’nevah I“
.dias retsnom eht ”,seY“
.efil sih ni neeb reve dah ti naht redrah kcoc sih gnikam dna
.emac ruatonim eht sa
”!reidlos ,ti oD .em rof muC“
.taeh esnetni htiw gnimmurht ydob elohw sih tnes ti sa
,emahs ni daeh sih no drawkcab dedlof srae siH
,scep sti no riah ydob esraoc
.railimaf si tnecs ruoy ,hturt nI“
.gniniart reidlos sih gnirud selbats eht gninaelc nehw
.delaever yllanif saw ecaf s’soroB sa
kcid nam-llub fo teef owt ylraen eht dnuora scep s'soroB bur dna pirg ot sdnah sih pu gnihcaer
.erised htiw dehsulf tsehc dna ecaf
.sselhceeps saw dnumgiS ”?tahw-
.sraj fo lluf sevlehs eht ot devom eh sa
eciov gnilworg s’erutaerc eht dnim reven
.sevooh kcalb fo riap a ni dedne dna
tnemevom hcae htiw hguone tsuj meht gnidaerps
.shtaerb gnitnap hguorht dias soroB ”,revo lloR“
.erutaerc eht dneffo ot ton gniyrt ,dias eh
etubirt naelcnu nA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,mih etadimitni ot hguone saw enola etteuohlis s’tsaeb eht fo ezis ehT .srovaf lauxes
tfahs kciht s’dnumgiS depolevne
sba s’reidlos eht gnola deggard eugnot dna eson sih
stnemom wef a rof tnelis saw dnumgiS
noisneherppa eht morf ylno ton
,skeehc dna nihc sih tuoba ylurnu dna dliw saw ti hguoht
otno lio gnizilatnat eht fo erom derehtals ruatonim eht dna
seye sih desolc dnumgiS
”?gniog er’uoy erehw llet uoy nac woH“
.moor rehto eht ni tuoba gnippolc
.smra yriah yllauqe dna
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
,moordeb eht otni tuo kcab dnumgiS del dna
”,nam elttil ,eurt t’nsi taht wonk htob eW“
emarf rood eht dniheb raeppasid erugif gnikirts s’soroB dehctaw eh sa
detaerc saw noitidart etubirt eht
.daeh s’dnumgiS dellif
,detaropave toof sih ni niap ehT
”.ti dniheb yrotsih eht uoy thguat etubirt fo noitidart eht taht thguoht evah dluow I“
desuap tsaeb ehT
.yawa deniard ylwols retaw eht dna
,citore yrev saw tsaeb eht yb dehsaw gnieb taht
,tsehc sih ot seenk sih dehctulc eh dna srae sih dehcaer osla
.tnemwodne gnol-toof tsomla
.ylesraoh dekaorc eH
”!ecnesse ruoy em eviG .ti s’tahT“
.htgnel sih fo ffo dellup tsaeb eht sa
,pmur gnittis s’ruatonim eht teem ot spih sih detfil eH
,debborht tfahs htommam eht sa eugnot sih tih
.sraey derdnuh-owt ylraen rof ereh neeb evah I ,feirb eb oT“
,deretne dah yeht erehw llaw eht raen sa llew sa
”...dnoceS eht soraT gniK
deraeppasid ruf eht ,kcen sih woleB
.ecnesse sih htiw etihw eugnot detnelat taht gnitniap
.denruhc sllab s’dnumgiS
,yksum eht pu dekcip eson nwo siH
.dnumgiS fo pot no gnitnap dna
kcab s’reidlos eht no dnah mrif a decalp dna dewollof soroB
emoh ym denaforp uoy evah yhW“
dias eciov gnisopmi ,peed a
kcoc s’dnumgiS fo esab eht dnuora eloh sih dehcnelc ylpmis dna
sba s’dnumgiS tfel reven kcas ytfeh s’ruatonim ehT
.edisni sehcni xis ylraen knus ti sa denekciht dna dehtirw elcsum laro eht sa
.sih ot spil s’ruatonim eht dellup dna
.dlehpu eb tsum niagrab eht tub
daeh sih fo sedis eht morf tuo kcuts srae talf siH
dna kcid sih no stops thgir eht fo lla revo gnibbur saw
”.soroB em llac yam uoY“
no deloord ti sa deslup
,egral a dah roolf enots ehT
.tsehc s’dnumgiS otno deppird dna debborht kcoc nwo sih dna
.retaw eht rednu deppils dna
s’tsaeb eht ni gnikaerb kcen s’tidnab eht fo hcnurc gninekcis ehT
.eugnot tfos eht ta lasuora gniworg ylkciuq sih fo etips ni
liart esraoc a otni denrut
.llat teef enin ro thgie ylbaborp saw soroB taht desseug dnumgiS
yawrood eht hguorht nam-llub ,egral eht hctaw ot kcen sih denarc dnumgiS
.ssenkrad eht hguorht namuh gnipmil
.ekops eh sa bmuht kciht a htiw yldi redluohs s’dnumgiS debbur soroB
.detfaw llems suoiciled a hcihw morf lwob a dna
,nwod kcab tas ruatonim eht sa
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
sredluohs dna tsehc s’dnumgiS tuoba deffins eson s'soroB
tsehc ralucsum ,yzzuf
.eurt t’nsaw taht spahrep ,lleW
.gnibbur suorogiv htiw ti ni pu mih depparw ruatonim eht dna
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
niaga gnicar nageb traeh siH
.spih sih morf meht erot ylsseltroffe retsnom eht sa depsag eh dna
.llaw eht tsniaga ylmrif kcab sih dehsup dna redluohs sih debbarg dnah ekil-namuh ,hguor
yad eht gnirud enob eht ot dnumgiS dekrow dah ohw rotcurtsni llird a saw eH
,dnumgiS ,emit tsaL
.regnol neve worg dna
renroc a denrut soroB
.ylthgit sredluohs s’dnumgiS deppirg dna nwod dehcaer eh sa eciov gnireenimod
.deifirup ton erew uoY“
.dednammoc soroB ”,esniR“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
nemes ruatonim fo strups lufrewop neetneves sa
.eson sih hguorht gnitrons dna gnitnap
,daerps dluow sromur taht larutan ylno si tI
,deeps sih desaercni ruatonim ehT
.strac eht gnidraug eb ot desoppus saw dna
,dekcil dna dekcus erutaerc eht sa detnap dna deffuh dnumgiS
tfahs sih fo esab eht ot ylthgit pu dellup sllab sih sa
noitasnes eht morf desnet yletaidemmi selcsum s’dnumgiS
kaew seenk sih edam
dnoceS eht soraT
.yromem sih ni gnar llits sdnah erab
emit lanif eno tas ruatonim ehT
,godknitS yb ”etubirT s’ruatoniM A“
daeh talf eht revo nar eugnot siH
evissam esoht ni
.sreyals retsnom eb-dluow tsniaga draug ot
mra s’dnumgiS debbarg retsnom ehT
.detiaw eh elihw flesmih htiw od ot tahw fo erusnu
tug sih revo dewolf taht
.enot evitatirohtua taht ni dednammoc soroB ”,deb eht no teG“  .deksa eh
,sgel sih nwod strohs rehtael sih deggut soroB sa dehctaw dnumgiS
,ecnatsbus kcils eht ni
kcoc gninetfos s’dnumgiS dnuora erofeb naht rethgit neve dehcnelc elohssa siH
,emarf egral s’erutaerc eht morf detfaw taht tnecs enilucsam
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,meht dellor dna skeehc ttub s’namuh rellams eht deppirg sdnah lufrewop sih
,daed era yeht won dnA“
”.sey ,htaed s’gnik eht litnU“
”,tnecs ruoy wonk I“
dehctiwt kcoc s’dnumgiS
ssilb ni denaorg hcae dna
.fo erac nekat llew saw soroB taht nees ylniatrec dah
,eno gnizilatnat a saw tsaeb eht htiw xes fo tcepsorp eht elihw dna
,eloh s’dnumgiS fo tuo dna ni derehtils eugnot sih sa
denruter taht ruf nworb eht rof tpecxe lamron erew sgel s’soroB
stidnab eht epacse ot deganam dnumgiS erehw regnahffilc a no dedne eW
.deddon ruatonim ehT  .dias dnumgiS
elttek lluf rehtona htiw
,egral a dna yrotaval a dleh taht moor rellams a otni dna
seye s’retsnom regral eht otni kool ot daeh sih denrut eH ”.llet dluoc I“
,snroh devruc ,deroloc-yrovi
.erusaelp htiw deffuh dna
,kciht s’tsaeb eht revo dnah a nar ylsuoiruc dnumgiS
.draeb namuh a ekil
s’retsnom eht ni esolc os dleh gnieb morf derettulf traeh s’dnumgiS
htmraw eht ni yldetnetnoc detaolf eh dna
.mih rof dennalp dah soroB esle revetahw fo sthguoht dwel eht morf osla tub
kcoc sih gniklim eloh lufrednow eht dna
,tuo nar elttek eht nehW
mih rednu deneffits dna debborht noitcere siH
.eye tfel sih fo tfel eht ot ylerab tsuj ruf eht ekorb rehtona dna
”?siht od ot gniog yllaer ew era-
”?won sneppah tahW“
kooh a no elttek eht decalp eh sa
but eht fo tuo debmilc eh sa mih rof lewot loow a dleh soroB
mrof enilucsam s’tsaeb eht fo noitarimda sih morf dnumgiS gnitloj
.elohssa gnihcnelc s’soroB otni peed detpure dna
”.esnes htxis a ti llaC“
hteet sih dehcnelc eH
,enots eht otno derettalps
,dedne xamilc s'soroB ,yllautnevE
.selcsum derit dna
,stros fo enam nworb krad a dah nam-llub eht dna
selcsum gniredduhs s'soroB debbur eH
,degrembus saw eh elihw dellup gnieb nisab eht fo dne rehto eht ta gulp eht draeh eH
dnumgiS dednimer
”…gnicrof hcum od ot evah t’now uoy spahreP“
ecalperif enots a raen riahcmra gnikool-elbatrofmoc a osla saw erehT
,hctorc s’tsaeb eht degguh taht strohs rehtael fo riap a fo tsiaw eht rednu nwod dna
s’llub a ekil kciht
.noitrexe suoiverp s’retsnom eht ot eud
.hcuot s’ruatonim eht ta ydob sih hguorht gnillor erusaelp eht dna
.ecaf lamina na hcus ni
,wam gniffuh s’tsaeb eht otni nemes kciht detpure kcoc siH
naorg a hguorht dias dnumgiS
eseht piks nac uoy
sdrow gnidnammoc s’tsaeb ehT
.tnemeerga eht ekorb uoY“
,yag gnitirw neeb sah ohw
tsehc sih ni dednuop traeh s’dnumgiS
snroh s’retsnom eht deppirg dnumgiS
ydob gnireviuq s’dnumgiS fo hcni yreve revoc ot erus edam ruatonim ehT
,mih deird lewot eht sa
.gnihton dah dnumgiS
,redluohs sih no dnah a decalp soroB sA
dehctiwt stun sih sa deirc dnumgiS
.did eh fi mih eveileb dluow erutaerc eht detbuod eh dna
.ecaf s’reidlos eht gnola tperc nirg A
.nam-llub regae eht otni zzij tnetop ,kciht detrups dna deredduhs
,denot s’reidlos eht debbur dnah hguor
.htgnel gnibborht s’namuh eht no tas dna
”!ris ,sey-Y“  .delworg soroB
,yltpurba deppots soroB
.tfahs gnibborht sih revo gnidils won eugnot eht fo gnileef eht morf skeehc sih ot hsur
yltneg kcab s’reidlos eht debbur soroB
.niks sih otno delbbird diuqil looc sa depsag neht dna
”.dellems dnoceS eht soraT gniK yaw eht fo em dnimer uoY
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,godknitS yb
”?krad eht ni ees yllautca t’nac uoy tuB“
,ediskcab s’dnumgiS fo hcni yreve derevoc lio eht taht deifsitas saw soroB ecnO
,evisserpmi sih woleb tsuj
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
namuh rellams eht morf yawa taem sih dehcnerw nam-llub eht
.ylleb ygdup sih nwod dna
,llaw rehtie no decalp sehcrot dna
yltfos dias dnumgiS
srallip elbram devrac fo riap a dessap yehT
eloh denethgit s’nam-llub eht fo tuo deppils dah
sdnah ytaem s’soroB sa
.evig ot tfel dah eh gniht eno eht fo thguoht eht ta
.yawllah enots eht fo ria pmad eht ni dehctiwt taht eson nworb ,ediw a htiw dna
.selcsum sih otni lio tnargarf eht degassam
,dliw mih gnivird saw tnecs eht tub
.ruatonim lacol a rof etubirt gniraeb navarac a gnidraug saw
mih revo dehcuorc ruatonim eht
odnecserc a ot gnisir eciov gninaorg sih
,mih evoba detnap soroB
.dlog dna der ni tserc layor soraT eht gnitciped
.nekat neeb dah eh erehw ta dnuora kool ot mih gnisuac dna
gniredduhs ruatonim eht gnivael
elttob a morf pop kroc a draeh dnumgiS
,sraey neetruof ylraen rof tums cihpromoporhtna
stonk ni flesti deit hcamots sih dna
sgnireffo erupmi htiw
timda ot dah reidlos ehT
,yhw wonk t’ndid namuh ehT
.niorg sih ot denruter taht ssenffits eht pleh t’ndluoc eh dna
but eht ni tas dnumgiS
,gnicanem taht ni delworg eh
”?yademos nruter ot ekil uoy dluow-
”.yletelpmoc hturt eht ekatrevo dluow yeht taht ezilaer t’ndid tsuj I
”.ti evig ot uoy ecrof tsum I snaem ti fi neve
,egral a nehw taorht sih otni pu depael traeh s’dnumgiS  2 fo
llew sa ti morf gnitaidar taeh eht leef dluoc eh dna
”?em eraps uoy did yhW“
,gnol a erofeb dias tsaeb eht
riah tsehc s’soroB
mih hguorht drawnwod delevart tI
,egral taht sa erusaelp htiw tsehc sti ni wol gnilbmur
.decar dnim s’dnumgiS
.yrruF oS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
eltsep dna ratrom gnidnirg a fo dnuos ehT
elddup llams a otni retaw eht fo emos deruop eh sa dias soroB
fo trap lanif dna
.doohnam gnislup sih dnuora flesti depparw eugnot eht dna
rethgirb emaceb thgil ehT
.thgin ta mih dekcuf neht dna
tes gnieb etipsed namuh ylgnisirprus erew yeht taht deciton dna
namuh rellams eht sa
”.ti fo draeh reven I ,did ehs fI“
”?neht ti s’taht oS“
dessik namuh rellams ehT
”!eman ruoy wonk neve t’nod I ,no dloh ,yeH !wO“
,tsul deldirbnu htiw dnim sih gnillif
.navarac ruo dialyaw yehT“
,gnissorc redrob ybraen eht fo noitcetorp ym rof egnahcxe ni os ,em ot detbedni saw gnik ehT .enif s’ti ,oN“
.but eht fo dne rehto eht ta
,gnibborht s’dnumgiS dehctaw soroB
.deen dna tsul dnuofwen htiw deleer
sesnes s’reidlos eht dna
.mih fo edisni ti decrof nam-llub eht fi gnirevocer on eb dluow erehT .kcid tnaig
I deeN“  .ybraen roolf eht morf elttek ssarb elbazis a pu dekcip dna
.llaw dnah-tfel eht otni tes saw hcihw
.ecaf sih morf sehcni gnibborht
W“  .selppin gninedrah yltfiws sih revo dna
,mih edavni eugnot s'soroB fo ssentew eht tlef eh sa
.revo nrut ot deirt eh nehw
.elpmet eht fo sllah ekil-ezam
,gnihtyna od ro yas dluoc dnumgiS erofeb ,neht dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,hguoht taht tuoba kniht ot emit evah t’ndid eH ?ruf …sih dna
.mih deffins erutaerc eht sa
nemodba s’dnumgiS otno mucerp rieht gnippird
kcoc s’reidlos ehT
”.yfsitas ton seod
”.etubirt enif a ekam lliw uoY“
sredluohs s’reidlos eht revo gnikrow
dlot saw eh sa did dnumgiS
feiler htiw naom dnumgiS gnikam
eerf eugnot sih dellup soroB
.hcamots dna tsehc sih
soraT fo modgnik eht morf reidlos a ma I
smotsuc s’tsaeb eht fo gnihton wenk dnumgiS
”.gnihton evah I …I“
”.deifsitas neeb sah tnemeerga ehT
ylippah eson sih hguorht gniffuh
.detnurg soroB dna
.tsehc sih ot pu dna
,eludehcs no gnireffo etairporppa eht htiw uoy tneserp ot yaw ruo no erew eW
elttek gnimaets eht htiw denruter soroB
,etubirt eht morf edisa
.gniraedne ti dnif tub pleh t’ndluoc dnumgiS
,gnizoo ot dewols msagro sih sa detnap dnumgiS
”?huh ,lleweraf a sa hcum os ton htiw tuo em kcik neht dna odlid a ekil em esu tsuj ll’uoY“
2 traP ,godknitS yb
,selcsum s’dnumgiS xaler dna
.niks erab sih revo gnilffins nageb tuons ekil-woc ,egnarts a nehT
.ylevissessop mih revo mra yriah
,nisab eht ot txen deleenk neht dna
,htgnel yniev eht dekorts sdnah sih dna
,sredluohs s’dnumgiS ot pu kcab sdnah sih devom eh sA
hguorht emoc dah yeht rood nedoow ,egral eht morf edisa
.tnemesuma ni detrons soroB  .deksa dnumgiS
”etubirT s’ruatoniM A“   :yojne esaelP
.tfahs gnibborht s’dnumgiS dnuora gnihcnelc dna
tseretni hcum htiw tfahs gnippird
!lluf nmad os tlef ydaerla stun sih tub
efil ym denetaerht dna
”…ydaerla ev’uoy tuB ?tahW“
.did eh sa dnumgiS revo lwob eht fo stnetnoc eht gnilknirps
tnurg gnipsag a tuo tel eH
.s’namuh rellams eht otni desserp
denaom dnumgiS ”!esolc m’I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,eil ot gniyrt morf niag ot gnihton dah eH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,tuons derruf-nworb A
.retaw gnimaets eht htiw but eht gnillif nageb dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.redlob ylthgils leef ot nageb dnumgiS dna
.revol namuh sih ot txen nwod flesmih dial ylregnig soroB dna
em tpecxe enoyreve dellik yeht tub
.elkcirt gnizoo na ot dewols msagro s’dnumgiS litnu
.daeha yawllah eht nwod thgil mid a ees dluoc dnumgiS dna
.srevocdeb niks-lamina eht otno pu delwarc ylwols dna deplug dnumgiS
”,toh oot t’nsi siht epoh I“
.tsehc yriah ,ralucsum yrev sti tsniaga deldarc saw eh dna
.thgilerif gnirekcilf eht ni elkraps ot seye nedlog s’soroB desuac hcihw
,dekan eht gnillup nageb dna
,ssik eht ekorb soroB
detrap shtuom riehT
htuom yrgnuh taht otni daol eritne sih gniward
deb esnemmi na raen moor eht tuoba tas
.kaeps dluoc retsnom eht taht aedi eht deredisnoc neve reven dah eH
”etubirT s’ruatoniM A“
roolf eht no lewot pmad eht dessot eh sa deggurhs soroB
pit eht ta talf saw tI
.tuo deird ylkciuq htuom sih dna
W“  ”.erofeb semit eerht ereh neeb evah uoY“
,pmad s’dnumgiS ssorca gnivom erofeb tip ytaews won sih otni ylthgils gnippid
deldarc gnieb saw dnumgiS erehw tsap nwod deunitnoc dna scep s’tsaeb eht derevoc
.llaw eht otni redluohs sih desserp ylmrif llits taht dnah egral eht dna
,deklat gniht eht tub
enam s'soroB deppirg dnumgiS
ewa ni dehctaw dnumgiS
.elbadnatsrednu s’tahT“
.noitasnes egnarts eht morf drah worg ot ton delggurts eh sa
ssenkrad eht ni skeehc s’dnumgiS deroloc emahs dna
sdnah detnelat sih
,tsehc gnivaeh s’ruatonim eht ta delevram dnumgiS
.yawa teef lareves gnidnal ti fo hcum
,egral a decalp soroB dna wolgretfa eht ni deksab eh sa dehgis dnumgiS
.detrons tsaeb ehT
.daeh s’dnumgiS revo ti fo emos deruop dna
,rehto hcae ot txen debborht skcoc riehT
pu dekool dnumgiS dna
eugnot gnizilatnat eht esuaceb
?tey daed eh t’nsaw yhW .ezorf dnumgiS
ecnahc yb nees dah dnumgiS taht sesroh fo snoitcere eht ekil hcum ,gnir laidem gnislup a dah dna
W …I“ .ssenlufhsab dna terger fo ksam suoetip a otni denrut ecaf sih dna
roolf eht no elttek eht decalp soroB
gnizeeuqs eloh sih
egassap gnihcnelc ,thgit ,mraw ehT
.delkcuhc soroB
.mih ta delims soroB
”.naem uoy tahw s’taht fi seye ym esu t’nod I“
tsehc ytaews sih gnola deggard eugnot kciht
.ylwols reidlos eht gnikorts
tfahs sih desaeler soroB
.ereht eb ot tnaem saw kcoc s’namuh eht ekil
,smra sih no selcsum kciht eht etipsed ylleb ygdup a dah soroB taht was reidlos ehT .erif eht evoba
yllacimhtyhr dehcnelc elohssa sih sa dednamed soroB
dnah sih otno lio eht fo emos deruop eH
”.ecnegilletni rieht fo snamuh ecnivnoc ot elttil od yllacipyt sretsnoM
,stnemevom rieht ni esnetni dna mrif werg sdnah gnigassam siH
”.etubirt em eviG .yob ,muC“
,rial s’ruatonim eht ot meht dael ot mih decrof dna
dereffo dnumgiS fi od dluow erutaerc eht tahw erus t’nsaw eH
renosirp dnumgiS koot ohw stidnab yb dialyaw saw navarac ehT
erohw a ekil duola naom dnumgiS edam
”,emuserp I ,srevol erew uoy fo owt eht dnA“
”?wonk neeuq eht diD“
sevlehskoob lareveS
ti hguorht dnumgiS deirrac soroB
.llaw dnah-thgir eht no yawrood rehtona saw
.toof sih htiw ti detset dnumgiS
,ti fo edisrednu eht pu dna smra sih fo eno nwod devom eson ehT
”?epacse ot tpmetta uoy dluohs neppah lliw tahw fo uoy dnimer
tsehc yvaeh s'soroB dna rehtona eno tuoba dellor seugnot rieht sa
soraT fo modgniK eht rof reidlos a
,stnap sih ni drah kcor kcoc sih gnikam saw yromem ehT
.eb reve dluoc namuh a naht regral hcum saw eh hguoht ,deunitnoc ydob namuh ,lamron a dna
emit tsrif eht rof lluf ni retsnom eht gniees fo thguoht eh sa
,dimit dna teiuq emoceb dah eciov siH
s’ruatonim eht fo thgis eht ta htuom sih morf emac taht psag teiuq eht pleh t’ndluoc dna
.tsehc dna ,kcab ,sredluohs
.kcab sih revo nwod neht dna
”.egamirglip txen eht erofeb semit ynam nruter ot epoh I ,em eveileB“
.niks sih morf detfil eson eht sa
.nisab gnihsaw ssarb
.daeh sih koohs dnumgiS
.tsehc ylrub eht morf elbmur desaelp a desuac hcihw
.meht dnuora sllaw enots eht fo ffo deohce spets-fooh gnippolc s’tsaeb eht sa
,ti htiw kcid s’dnumgiS deppirg dna
.tsurht hcae htiw tuons sih drawot ttub sih gnitfil nageb namuh eht nehw
.selcsum s’revol rellams sih degassam eh sa
”!niagrab eht fo trap t’nsi siht ,tiaw-
taht htiw flah ni mih tilps dluow soroB
noitcere kciht s’ruatonim ehT .woleb deen dna
mraerof gnorts s’nam-llub eht dekcil dna
”?etubirt ruoy rof ylno ti sI“ .deksa eH
.eciov sih ni noitangidni eht edih ot elbanu saw dnumgiS
.deksa eh ”?ereh devil uoy evah gnol woH“
.moor eht gnivael erofeb mih ta yldnik delims neht dna deddon soroB
.deb eht ot txen roolf eht otno detpure ti sa gniwolleb
mih otni decrof gnieb gniht taht fo thguoht ehT
.ydob derit sih morf emirg eht leep ti gnittel
.ylleb ygdup s'soroB debbur yldi dnumgiS
?reverof ereh mih peek ot nalp soroB diD
lio ydaeh eht detsat soroB dna eh sa
.deb eht drawot ylgnigaruocne gnirutseg
toof sih ni ehca gnibborht eht tsniaga
...tcefrep yllautca s’taht-hT“
,htuom s'soroB ni muc dah eh ecnis gnol neeb t’ndah tI
.eciov sih ot gninruter ecanem eht ,deksa soroB
”,seiromem dab pu gnirb ot gnidnetni t’nsaw I ,yrroS“
soroB draeh eh sa
duola depsag dnumgiS
riah ydob esraoC
snihs sih nwod yawflah
”,ssenregae …ym evigroF“
.eciov sti fo enot eht deroloc ssendas dna
.dleh ti muc suoiciled hcum woh fo thguoht eht ta retaw
ecarbme eltneg ylgnisirprus
.hgiht s’dnumgiS tsniaga detser dna
.deb eht no nwod mih dleh dnah evissam eno sa
.efil sih fo tser eht rof evitpac dleh eb ot tnaw yltcaxe t’ndid eh
,drawpu flesmih detfil soroB nehW
nisab eht ni nwod dnumgiS tes soroB
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
,krad eht hguorht deppolc soroB sa
”,tnaw I tahw em eviG“
.syad gniniart sih morf emalf dlo na fo
ssenizzid dna taeh fo hsur a
,gninraw tuohtiw dna
.ylyrd delkcuhc soroB  .dias dnumgiS
,etubirt evah lliw I
.sbreh dna doof fo lluf sraj nosam dekroc htiw dekcats sevlehs
.doohnam suortsnom ’soroB fo tils eht ta kcil ot daeh sih detfil eh dna
,deb evissam eht otno mih gnigru
taeh nosmirc tlef eh sa
.kcaba nekat ylraelc saw soroB
.degrembus flah ylno dnumgiS gnivael
”…erusaert erom meht evig t’ndid I fi