”?rehtegot gnivil s’woh oS“
,tnemom a rof nwod gnikool seye reH
.ylhsipeehs elttil a delims ehS .dennirg einnA
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,dennirg tac llams ehT .dias emiaJ ”!yeH“
.mih gnissik dna kcoc sih no gnimmuc emit eht fo tser eht tneps I oS“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.lamron rieht naht htoob tnereffid a ni gnittis sdneirf reh fo puorg eht was ehs litnu éfac eht revo dennacs seye reH
.haeL ,efiw reh tsniaga denael
.em ekat dna emoh tog eh tnemom eht em barg ot
.gniog laem ecin siht dah d’eh dna emoh emac I
,ti tuoba gnihtemos dnA
.taorht reh deraelc dna seye s’emiaJ otni thgiarts dekool einnA
saw od ot detnaw yllaer ,yllaer tahw taht em dlot flow yknik eht
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
,llaw eht otni em dekcuf ylwols eh dna mih rof gnipsag saw I
.pu denaelc tog tsuj ew dna rewohs eht ot em koot eh ,sdrawretfA
.slrig fo puorg eht ta delims dna reh ediseb taes eht otni dils eH
.tnemom a rof ralloc reh ot tnew dnah s’einnA
”?thgir ,nekorb eb ot sah gniht taht ,naem I“
eht dna ssa ym tsniaga eugnot dloc a leef I ,wonk I gniht txen eht dna nwod seitnap ym gnillup s’eH
,dias neG ”?tahw neht oS“
,tahw ,dna emoh semoc tsuj eh oS“
.em edisni decrof saw kcoc sih dna nwod erew seitnap ym litnu gnineppah saw tahw wonk t’ndid I
.shgiht ym nwod gninnur s’ti dna ecaf sih fo ssem a gnikam m’I litnu
”,haey ,krapllab taht ni …yletinifed saw ti tub tib elttil a kcart tsol I …naem I“
.drah em gnibbur mih ot pu ekow I
”.gnimocni yotyob
.eveiveneG saw einnA ot txeN
.erom raeh ot gnitnaw ,dneirf reh ta delims ehs tub toh gninrub erew skeehc s’nooccar ehT .drawrof gninael
.won shtnom wef a rof ksa ot gnitnaw saw eh
…fo tros tsuj I .puY“
.reh ta kcab detcerid noitnetta eht ta detliw srae reH .dias neG
…tsuj ti did oS .ruof s’tahT“
,043 ot pu s’taht ,lleW“
.dias neG ”!tihslluB“
tub eurt s’ti kniht yllaer t’nod I dna semitemos teews os s’eh …si llabnroc ehT“
.moordeb eht ni teg
.esle gnihtyna tuoba erac ot mees t’nseod eh tuB
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.reh ot txen htoob eht no nwod esrup reh gnittes ,elbat eht ot revo tnew tub tnemom a rof denworf ehS
!cilbup ni siht tuoba gniklat fo aedi erem eht ta gninrub skeehc reh
.ydaerla secaps gnirahs tuoba tol a deklat ev’ew dna gnihtyreve gninaelc ta doog yllaer neeb s’eH
.syaw htob ti evol seod yllaer eh esuaceB
”.emac eh erofeb eciwt mih no emac I
,nwod deppord srae
.drawrof denael dna
,krow htiw enod saw I retfA
.nwod yaw eht lla em dleh tsuj eh tib elttil a retfa tuB
.puorg eht hguorht gnar ecnetnes reh fo ytilanif ehT
neht dna ereht pu hsinif ot em dlot dna yawa dellup eh tuB
.ecalkcen reh ees ot nwod decnalg einnA
ffo gniyrd erew ew nehw em dnuora smra depparw eH
.delims dna ni denael haeL
.sgnab reh yb deduolc seye reH
.dneirf rieht ta delims slrig ehT
.tib a retfa gniggaw liat sih
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dias neG ”?kcuf eht tahW“
.doog s’tI“  .delims haeL
”.taht ylesicerp od dluoc eh taht deerga I dnA
.dias emiaJ ”?gniog peek
”?ecalp wen eht s’woH ?uoy era woH“
.kcen dna kcab ym revo gnissik ,em dleh tsuj eH
.retal ti od d’eh gniyas ,knis eht ni sehsid eht tup eh dna rennid htiw pu dehsinif eW“
”.ti yllacisab s’tahT“
,yeh hO“ .daeh reh koohs dna dehgual tsuj haeL
.sredluohs reh revo dna daeh reh nwod dedacsac taht riah ylruc gnol htiw nooccar yhs a saw neG
.em ta gnikool tuo kcoc sih htiw ereht gnidnats mih ees tsuj I dna
.noitamriffa ni daeh reh deddon tsuj eilloc eht tub
”emaG s’rebmuN A“:yojne esaelP
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”.rehtegot VT hctaw ot tnew ew dna
.sgel dennat reh fo erom ffo gniwohs dna
.dias einnA ”,puY“
.em regnif ot detrats dratsab eht neht tuB
.htuom ym ni kcoc sih koot dna nwod tlenk tsuj I
.tluaf s’boj sih lla yllacisab s’ti ,oS“
.sdnah sih ni yttup saw I dna drah debbur eh oS
”?syad owt ni smsagro nezod owt revo dah uoY“  .reteiuq hcum
.saw I lrig doog a tahw dna em devol eh hcum woh em gnillet dna keehc ym gnihsurb tpek eh dna yppah os saw eH
.retteb leef mih pleh
.ssem a hcus saw eh esuaceb kcab dneirfyob ym detnaw tsuj I dna ti yb das os saw I .erehwesle dnim ,esnet syawla saw ydob siH
”.drah taht ton s’ti …oS
.mih rof gninihw dna liat ym gniggaw ,ereht gnidnats
.emit eht lla desserts emoh gnimoc saw eH
.noitarimda dna rorroh neewteb erehwemos dneirf reh ta gnirats ,dias emiaJ
.yaw siht mih gniees detah tsuj I
…fo tros tsuj I taht tcerid
.deggurhs dna pil reh tib ehS
,noitasrevnoc rieht gniraehrevo yllaer saw eno on erus ekam ot gniyrt ,dnuora gnicnalg saw einnA
.yltsenoh ,taerg yllaer neeb s’tI“
reh htiw yaws ti gnikam ,gaw a evag
.revihs thgil a evag dna pil reh tib ehS
.krow ta gnihtyreve dna yad sih tuoba em gnillet s’eh ,sdrawretfa oS
.esle gnihtemos …saw rewop gniyats gnikcuf sih dna lufrewop dna gnorts os saw tI
”?ti s’tahT“ .reh ta denworf haeL
.thgirpu gnidnats kcoc sih
,ecnetsisni rieht ta denworf eilloc eht
…si eugnot sih esuaceb gnimriuqs m’I dna gnikahs era sgel yM
”?tuoba gniklat uoy erew tahW“ .demaeb eh ”,oS“
”?won ta rebmun eht s’tahW“
.sdneirf reh morf ti erucsbo ot gniyrt ,gat eht htiw deyalp ehS
”.ynam taht dah uoy yaw on s’erehT .taht no tihsllub llac attog I ,haeY“
”.ylteiuQ“ .dessih haeL
”!emiaJ“  “—nezod owt revo dah uoy em gnillet ylsuoires uoy erA
.ralloc reh morf gat esool eht ta drah gnirats ,ni deworran seye reH
.ni dils eh tnemom eht enod saw I emit eht yb taht pu dekrow os em tog eH
liat reH .dneirf reh htiw sgninrom yadrutaS tsom tneps ehs éfac llams eht dnuora dekool ehS
.daeh ym revo sdnah ym dah dna taht retfa deb eht ot nwod em dleh eH
.gnihtyna yas t’ndid I“ .nwod tlenk
.stit ym no gniggut erew hteet sih dna tsaerb ym no gnikcus saw htuom siH
si yrots s’yadot dna
.taht ekil derised gnieb evol I
.reh dnuora depparw smra s’nahtanoJ nehw dennirg dna reh dniheb decnalg einnA
s’einnA .953 dewohs yalpsid latigid ehT
.em no tceffe na evah sdrow esoht os god a llits m’I …naem I
.krow ta esnesnon laer emos htiw gnilaed saw eH
”,uoy rof llew ot gniog gnieb s’ti yppah yllaer m’I tuB
,ybigreK yb ”emaG s’rebmuN A“ saw sihT
.haeL ta decnalg dna desuap neht
os saw tI .rae ym ni gnilworg ,deb eht otni em dekcuf tsuj eH
hcum os no em denrut tsuj ti esuaceb ti tuoba naem os saw eH
.larutan yltcefrep saw ti ekil ,eta eh elihw gniog ti tpek eh tuB
.etamitni dna teews yllaer saw tI
”?tser eht tuoba tahw tub
?wonk’y ,ahpla na gnisaelp ekil I
.sehtolc ym morf tuo egnahc ot ecnahc eht teg neve t’ndid I
,dehsulf erew skeehc reH
,mih ta pu gnirats ,wols dna ecin mih dekcus I
tsuj m’I .revo yssup roop ym skrow dna ,nwot ot seog tsuj eh oS“
”.roolf driht eht ot pu ffuts ruo teg depleh yehT .sdneirf s’nahtanoJ dna ,ytluciffid ,ecneitaP“ ”?eganam
”?thgiE-ytfiF derdnuH eerhT …ekiL
pu em gnippal tsuj s’eH
tsuj eH .tnuoc tsol I emit ynam os gnimmuc saw I
.desufnoc os saw I
,deb eht no mih was dna ni deklaw I“
”.043 ot pu yaw eht lla saw rebmun eht ,retal ruoh na nwod saw tonk sih retfa tub ti fo kcart tsol I
,sdrawretfa skeehc ym no sdnah sih tup dna ylpeed em dessik eH“
.einnA ta gnirats saw neG
”.tcerroc s’tI …mu s’ti ,on-N“
.xes gnirud ronaemed sih ni yrav nac eh hcum woh ynnuf s’tI
,dnA .sih fo yerp …emos
.no gniog gniht citnamor ,gib siht dah tsuj dna ylrae elttil a tuo teg ot elba saw eH
.esnopser eht ta tahwemos gnillaf srae
.rehtnap emit-lluf dna ,retirw emit-trap a s’ohw
,denrub skeehc s’einnA
”?uoy ot od nahtanoJ did tahW“
”.dedeen I ffuts hcaer yllautca dluoc I os nehctik eht ni ffuts eht fo emos egnarraer em tel eh tub ,gnicnivnoc fo tib a koot ti dnA
.daeh reh gnikahs ,dias einnA
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
…emos saw I ekil em dleh
.htoob eht fo edis rieht no pu delruc meht fo owt eht ,dnah s’eimaJ no saw dnah s’haeL
.daeh reh deddon haeL  .delims ehs
.dlrow eht ni namow lufituaeb tsom eht saw I em dlot dna em ta pu delims
,deunitnoc dna denworf emiaJ
hguohT ”.won ti llet attog uoy ,yrots a pu tes uoY“ .dias haeL ”,oN“
?853 .yrros m’I“  .nemow rehto eht ot revo decnalg dna dneirf reh ta derats haeL ”…853 ,mU“ .toh gninrub skeehc ,dehsulb einnA ”,ho-O“
ot tsuj ,elttil a mih egassam ot gniyrt dna kcab sih gnibbur saw I ,thgin ta pu delruc erew ew nehw oS“
,ediw elttil a tnew seye riehT
”.ti tnaem eh llet dluoc I dna em ta dekool eh
.degnahc teg ot tnew dna yltfos em dessik
.sregnif sih fo ssem a edam dna ,niaga emac I
”.einnA ,enif eb ll’uoy dna ti ta peek tub thgif llits eW
uoy d’woH .rotavele na evah t’ndid otni devom uoy gnidliub eht draeh I“ .nwod kcab ti tes dna eeffoc reh fo pis a koot ehS .delims neG ”,dooG“
.lrig nooccar teiuq yllamron
.em devol eh hcum woh em gnillet dna ereht em gnidloh tsuj
.tib a pu naelc ot dah dna rennid gnihsinif ot kcab tnew I
.yzarc og ot gniog saw I thguoht I wols os tilc ym revo sregnif owt gninnur dna seitnap ym ni saw eH
.esirprus ni egral seye riehT
.foO“  .ti otni klim eht gniruop dna ssertiaw eht morf eeffoc eht gnitpecca ,delggig einnA
.elttil a delims neG
.moc.yrrufos.ybigrek//:sptth no
”?sruoh wef a ni semit net muc ot uoy tog eh oS“
taorht reh deraelc ehs
.tnemom a rof derevihs ehS
dna drah os em ta dekool tsuj eH
.saw ssuf gib eht tahw ees t’ndid ehS
”,wonk ot tnaw t’nod uoY“
.triks ym pu nur sdnah sih leef
,yltnerappa esuaceB“
…ekil erom tuB .gnihtyna ro edur ,ekil ,t’nsaw tI
”.syad owt ni smsagro thgie-ytnewt revo dah I“
.éfac eht otni deklaw ehs nehw deyaws sserd eulb trohs s’einnA   ybigreK yb
.kcab sdnah ym gnidloh
.rae reh dniheb riah dekcut dna dehgis einnA
tsuj eh dna gnidnammoc dna lamirp
.tsael eht yas ot detnelat
”.sseug I ,yawa deirrac elttil a tog I ,yrroS“
”… dna demialc os tlef I dna mih llems dluoc I
.em rof ydaer tsuj saw tI
?taht ekil pu gnipmuj rebmun reh ni laed gib eht s’tahW
.taht ekil pu delruc lla gnitae erew eW
.emit detimil a ni ti ot teg ot dah eh wenk dna noos krow ot dah eh
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.liat s’reveirter eht fo gniggaw etanoitceffa eht morf deggaw teg ot ton luferac ,haeL fo edis rehto eht no tas ehS
.thgin lla mih yb dekcuf tog
.ecaf reh morf yawa riah dehsurb eilloc redrob ehT
.llew yrev ffo em teg ot woh swonk eH“
tsuj saw dellems eh yaw eht dna erac eht htiw denibmoc ecrof eht
.emit elohw eht spil ym revo kcoc sih deggard dna bmuht sih htiw tilc ym dleh eH
”!yrots eht fo tser eht lleT
.ylisae taht ffo em tel t’ndid eh tuB“
eht ta dekool oirt ehT
.niffum reh fo etib a gnikat ,elbat eht otni denael ehS
dnuora nrut I .gnihtyreve dna si yad sih woh mih gniksa m’I dna emoh semoc eh ,yawynA“
tsuj I dna rehsawhsid eht ni ffuts emos gnittup m’I
.toh gninrub skeehc reh
,taht fo tib elttil a retfa ,oS“
…saw tI .em no emac dna tuo dellup eh nehw drah os emac I ,doG
”,raf os doog neeb yllaer s’ti tub nahtanoJ htiw ni devom I nehw detcepxe I tahw wonk t’ndid I
”?huh ,neht meht dah uoy ykcuL
.xif yletelpmoc reve ll’uoy gnihtemos ton s’tI“
.yalpsid DEL na dah taht ti no gat gnilgnad a htiw stros fo ecalkcen a eb ot raeppa dluoc ti taht hguone esool saw tI
!ffo sregnif sih naelc em edam eh nehw htaerb rof gnipsag llits saw I
.ti ta detniop dna tib elttil a daeh reh dekcoc ehS
,ybigreK yb ”emaG s’rebmuN A“
”!gnillats potS“ “—dna ffuts dna seiggev dna seldoon dna taem fo top suoiciled ,gib siht s’tI .ydaer rennid gnitteg tsuj ,evots eht ta ereht gnittis m’I oS“
!033 saw ti oga syad elpuoc a uoy was I nehW“
gnihtemos yas ot htuom reh denepo emiaJ
.eb yam ti gnissarrabme woh rettam on ,yllufhturt yrots eht llet ot flesreh devloser dah ehs tub dehsulf erew skeehc reH
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.llaw eht ot em dennip eh dna pu hsaw ot pu tog I
”.duts eht evol yllaer tsuj I“
!ffo em gnittel t’nsaw eh tub
”.eno rebmun saw tahT .hcum oot
.netfo erom retteb leef mih pleh ot detnaw I taht mih dlot I
,gninrom txen eht oS“
.tib elttil a pu dehsulf skeehc reh dna delims ehS
.gnirevihs dna mih gnidir tsuj m’I oS
.rednet os gnieb dna esolc os em gnidloh saw eH
.deksa haeL ”?eerf sdnaH“
.em gnisaet mih erudne ot dah tsuj I oS
!no emoC ?wor a ni semit thgie-ytnewt muc uoy litnu uoy skcuf
.0102 ecnis sdrapoel dna shateehc neewteb ecnereffid eht gninialpxe dna krow yrruf gnitirw neeb s’eH
.ysae syawla t’nsi taht ekil gnitacinummoc taht wonk I .doog s’tahT“
.tuo em gnitae si trevrep
.pot no debmilc I nehw em gnissik ,smra sih ni em dleh eH
.pu hsulf skeehc reh gnileef
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,pu em dellup eh ,lleW“
.tae ot ydaer gnitteg erew ew nehw pal sih otni em dellup eH
taht gnihtemos tuoba em ot gniklat detrats eh oS
.ecalkcen reh ta gnikool