,eb lliw reven ereht dna
,ecnetsixe rieht fo foorp doots taht stnemunom eht htiw gnola
,klof-renim erew yeht ,mrehS ekiL
.retteb diap strap nopaew gnitacirbaf nehw ton
.won esac taht kool t’ndid ti tub
,ksam sih fo sretlif yramirp eht detaemrep ydaerla dah goms eht fo sesag elitalov erom ehT
.ekila setaicossa dna sdneirf
,sdniw gnorts htiw delpuoC
enihcam tsav eht pu edam taht ynam fo tuo raeg a
.rettiwt//:sptth( floWisakiM yb ”enihcaM ehT fo traP A“
fo tpecnoc eht depoleved dah sreenigne fo ecnailla noitcaf-itlum a
.ytilaer a emoceb noitazilivic did secruoser fo gnirehtag eht hguorht ylno dna
.htiw krow ot gnihtyna evah gnol on dluow
,oot ti fo trap erew esle enoyreve dnA
,trap ralucitrap taht no tnedneped ylhgih emaceb ti
”.yad siht tsrif eht ton er’uoY“
.live yrassecen a sa ti was enoyreve
.werc tnemecalper a fo tnemtiurcer eht htiw gnola
erehpsomta eht otni devlossid erew taht slarenim dna slatem fo secart cinoi revetahw
,leets sselniats dna etercnoc tnatsiser-noisorroc fo snoitadnuof no tliub saw tI
,krow sih htiw drolraw dezarc-rewop emos fo troffe raw eht etingier yam eh taht os
,dellac netfo erew yeht sa ,sTMS ro ,snwoT gniniM dednepsuS eht detrats renoissimmoC eht ecnis revE
,suoregnad dna evisnepxe srovaedne hcus gnikam goms kciht ot eud denodnaba ylegral saw gninim desab-dnuorg ecnis revE
.devaeh ylleb sih sa
desimorp yrraB dlO .liat sih fo hctiwt a ylerab htiw ,ti ta kcab lwocs mrehS edam rotalitnev eht fo gniknalc A ?tsap eht fo ecnegruser rehtona eb yllaer raw tsuM ?dlrow eht fo sehsa
.sselesu saw enihcam eritne eht dna ,yawa trap ro raeg eno tsuj ekaT
.wap yb meht rehtag ot srenim eht gniwolla
dnuorgrednu eht ot nwod tnes gnieb erofeb ,slairetam war otni dessecorp rehtruf
,rewop rof selggurts gnidnereven ’snoitcaf ynam eht thguof taht snopaew eht otni edam saw leetS
,tuo detem ecneloiv
,sretrauq rieht dna sretlehs desab-dnuorg eht ot nekat dah
sknalp decrofnier-elbac eht ssorca
srebmahc citylatac
deman yltpa enicidem wolley eht deplug mrehS
,semuf suoixon ro lleh emoc ,degnahc reven elpoeP
shtnom eerht rehtona spahrep fo emitnwod a naem dluow siht dnA
,yteicos dliuber gnipleh osla saw eh yas dluoc eh dehsiw eH
.thgirpu tas mrehS .swonk ydoboN
,krow t’ndid enihcam eht nehw dnA
.tey sdoow eht fo tuo ton saw eh tuB
.repaehc semit ytnewt tuoba saw dna
.ecafrus eht no evivrus ot dedeen srellewdrednU stius ria eht htrof dehtrib
”enihcaM eht fo traP A“ saw sihT.yadot
,nwot nileppez eht no retlems derewop-dniw eht nihtiw stneutitsnoc esab sti otni deifirup saw sihT
ohw sioegruob eht rof riahc emos dliub neve ebyaM
.gniretaw eson dna seye
.rewop rof tsriht ehT
,elbitcurtsedni raen dna tsuboR
ecalp sih detalpmetnoc eh sa knird rehtona koot eH
.ti ni ecalp rieht dah lla
egduls cixot fo ssam derehtag ehT
,dekrow ti tub ,slacimehc dlohesuoh dna lairtsudni fo lluf saw deMraB fo giws a ,eruS
,skaep eht ffo tpews neeb dah detaf-lli eht tub
,tnatropmi oot raf deredisnoc snamuh fo sevil eht htiW
.emas eht deniamer hcum tub ,tsap eht fo sekatsim eht derebmemer sredael wen eht taht
,ynam fo troppus eht
,elpoep etarapsid eht etinu ot thguos emoS
.yad rehtona ehtaerb ot evil dluow eh taht won gniwonk
.ti fo kcis ylhguoroht saw mrehS
.smaerd erem dna ria no tliub t’nerew dlroW weN eht fo seitic eht
.evil ot tnaem saw
,elbac eht fo llup gnirussaer eht htiw egdirb suoiracerp eht revo gnilbmutS
,mih mlac dna bmun ot desu deMraB lanoisacco
,koorbtsuD fo mrehS ,eh fi dnA
.mad suoegaruoc a gnihcaerb nosiop fo revir a
.eznorb dna reppoc fo serutcurtsarfni htiw
.ecafrus eht no evil ot elbisaef regnol on saw ti taht tnerappa noos saw tI
deman secalp ,seirtsudni esoht rof ylelos snoiger emos dengissa snamuh eht oS
:yojne esaelP
.riaffa yliad neht
,ria deifirup fo slufgnul taerg ni deplug eH
.lavivrus s’ydob sih rof gnithgif ksam dna sgnul sih
.potrab eht otno deknilc
.selom owt htiw regdab yenoh a
.emit a ta rallip eno flesti dliuber dna
,srekrow-oc dna sdneirf tseb rieht fo rebmun a tsol dah srenim ehT
.retirw yrruF naeropagniS a , )floWisakiM/moc.rettiwt//:sptth(
,noisausrep lacinahcem yletelpmoc a fo smetsys tliub yehT
,revo saw ega latigid eht taht
,erusopmoc sti gniniager saw taorht sih ydaerlA
,ti xif ot strap rof tseuqer a tuo tnes dah eh taht
.tnetop sgniht lla htiw emac taht trofmoc eht ni neve mih llul ot deliaf ti won tub
reifirup gnul fo ssalg-tohs a yb deinapmocca lausu sih fo ssalg a
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,floWisakiM yb
,smrots latnemnorivne yldaed eht epacse ot etsah rieht ni woleb taerg eht ot nellaf dah rerafykS a ynaM
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.degnahc reven sgniht emos tub
ngised latnemadnuf rieht dna
,derucorp eb dluoc rotalitnev eht rof strap thgir eht litnu
.noitazilivic fo enobkcab eht deniamer taht seitic gnitaolf rehto dna
?rewop eurt eht dleiw won ssalc gnikrow eht t’ndluow
.snoitidnoc rehtaew gnidnuorrus yb yawa nrow t’nsaw egduls deziralop eht derusne srebmahc eht fo erutcurts ekilevac ehT
gnikohc dna gnitnap
meht no deiler taht skrowlatem ynam eht
.tihs ot gnihtyreve denrut noitagimuF eht ecnis reve ecneirepxe tabmoc fo rennam emos dah enoyreve tub
!sey...413...313...213 sretrauQ
.ytitnedi rieht rof thguof seitinummoc sa neve degreme snoitcaf wen dna
.rednetrab eht yrraB dekniw
.tliuber saw ti elihw detlah noitcudorp evah dluow
,rood eznorb dettip eht tsniaga yllufetarg denael eH
# .tneserp eht ni eid ot saw
.boj sti gniod liatkcoc tnevlos eht
eht morf pu sevlesmeht tfil ot ,sdrawot krow ot laog nommoc a dah yeht taht ees ton yeht dluoC .gniodnu nwo rieht ot latnemurtsni
.gniodnu rieht fo semuf eht epacse ot dnuorgrednu delf dlrow eht fo elpoep eht ,seloh rieht otni desahc star ekiL
.erew sgniht yaw eht saw tI
,noitaretilbo nwo rieht htiw aropsaid eht dewollof seitic dlo ehT .noitagimuF eht
ezilaer ot tsitneics a ekat t’ndid ti dna ,trapa llef stnenopmoc dna revo dettip stiucriC
,pets evarb eno taht ekat ot dah yteicos
srekrow fo rebmun A
srebmahc citylatac eht ni derehtag taht
.dne raf eht ta llaw eht tsniaga gninael srenim fo puorg a sdrawot elzzum sih dehctiwt knuks ehT
.delfits erew snoissime yrassecen sti dna seirotcaf eht
doolb dna liot eht yb detaerc saw tI
,htaerb sih deniager eh sa nevE
,stnemelttes eritne fo eslup eht emaceb smetsys gnihtaerb lacinahcem eseht
,sesunis gnitsetorp sih etipsed no ksam sih gnipeeK
,amiL tfarcreniM fo klof renim eht rof tuB
.knurd tsomla dekool yeht yas dluoc eno dna
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
.deppots reven raW
.srehto eht naht ecnatropmi erom dedleiw ti taht tniop eht ot
,dednuoser metsyS egruP kcolriA eht fo ssih eht
,xodarap derahs sti fo tuo yaw a dnuof yteicos tnemom ehT
.gniddib suoregnad erom rieht od ot detaerc erew sorhtna
,seirutnec eht yb suoixon werg meht dnuora ria ehT
,seilimaf no nwod gniraew elttab retfa elttab
,niaga os eb tonnac
yaw sih delbmuts regdab ehT
.ti nar taht sraeg laitnesse ynam eht fo eno saw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.rehtegot krow ot lla rof dnuorg nommoc eht
.syad eseht reppoc revo leets fo dnamed rehgih eht htiw ,gnisirprus toN
,deppots eb ot dah
,dias ecno nam esiw a sA
tsap gnol fo stcurtsnoc dna seitic eht nopu noitirtta fo sraey morf
.syad eerht ton rehtona htiw tcatnoc tsol dah tfarcreniM rieht ,tcaf nI
”enihcaM eht fo traP A“
.gnidliub rof dedeen eznorb eht rof reppoc hcum taht lla ecudorp t’ndid tfarc gninim sih tub
,woleb nwod tsol dna devil erew sevil ynam
.noitaixyhpsa ni llaw eht tsniaga gnispalloc-flah
dehsiw eh nehw syad erew erehT
.nettogeb dah stnapucco rieht ria ditef eht ot yerp gnillaf sedacaf leets dna etercnoc
,tuhs kcab ti wolb ot thguof mrots eht sa neve kcolria sih ot rood eht nepo gniknarC
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,ekirts no tnew yeht fI
delbmurc dah yteicos fo srallip dlo ehT
,efil enihcam decuder ,stcefed htriB
,elbaodnu eht odnu ot thguos srovivrus eht sA
,saw ecno taht tsap a fo stnanmer derettat eht otni gnilbmurc ylwols
tsap eht ni evil ot rof
deveileb ohw esoht erew erehT
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
hctocs sih fo tsal eht denwod regdab ehT
.demuser noitcudorp llit tsael ta ,dnuorg evoba dna woleb ngier dluow ecaep dna
,goms dirtup ,kciht eht hguorht sretrauq sih rof dekool sa hcum sa tlef neht
,eerf dellup renibarak sih sa yawgnag eht nwod dehsad mrehS
...llits tub ,slacimehc fo erutxim rehtona ylbaborP
,ti esu reven dluow eh gniveileb ,mih ot nwod dessap dah rehtaf sih lotsip dna
,erom shtnom wef a rof ehtaerb ot evil dna
,srenim wollef sih fo pleh eht htiw noitcudorp tlah dluoc
,noitarepsed dna noitavonni fo xim a hguorhT
derenrag yrtsudni hguorht yteicos dliuber ot thguos ohw esohT
fo senummoc naenarretbuS
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.senoZ tnatropmI yllaicremmoC
.ytissecen a emaceb edispot eht no seitilicaf gninim dna
rethgif deifirolg ot renim elbmuh ,enoyreve dna ,htaed dna efil fo elcric eht saw tI
.lufrewop dna hcir eht fo sreknub gniniatsus-fles eht ot delf ylegral gnivah ,ylppus trohs ni erew srotcod
dniknam woh saw sa
,stfahsknarc dna sraeg fo kcilc a htiW
.efil fo yaw nopu dedneped-revo dna dlo na htiw gnola
.efil wen a dnuof
.od tsum eh tahw wenk won eH .doots dna
worb depirts-kcalb sih tsniaga gnisnednoc detrats taews dekaerts-etalucitrap kcalb dna nworB
.dluow siht fo lla ,detsixe noitazilivic sa gnol sa roF .riapseD .noitulloP .raW
.noitavlas s’yteicos emaceb scinahcem dna sreenigne eht
.tenalp gniyd eht fo htaerb eht morf tsrow eht dereffus dlrow dlo eht fo scinortcele eht taht raelc saw ti
.sgniht fo emehcs dnarg eht ni
.neeb dah snoitazilivic rehto sseltnuoc sa tsuj
.hctocS noitatimi fo lufelzzum a gninwod erofeb thgir slirtson sih raelc ot htaerb peed a koot mrehS
.mih evoba gniliart elbac ytefas eht ot
.gnivil efas fo senituor gnimocrevo shtaed fo cifirroh tsom eht fo raef
noitinumma dna snopaew ,snug eht edam taht spohskrow ehT
.ti tuohguorht snoitartnecnoc lacimehc ni secnereffid eht yb detsefinam
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.pu hgih siht esned tsom eht erew
.sevil detaicerpparednu rieht ot dne tpurba na tnaem rotalitnev llams eno fo eruliaf eht
,ymonoce eht saw taht enihcam taerg eht nI
,edam staerht eb lliw erehT
,latem hguorht ria fo ezeehw prahs eht htiw dehguoc mrehS   floWisakiM yb
fi liaverp ton dluoc ecremmoc dna yrtsudnI
,nemow dna nem gnikrowdrah ynam fo
.srenim erom rof tseuqer rehtona ni tup ot namerof remialC eht tfel ylno siht dna
stalf nileppez gnirevoh eht neewteb dednepsus
floWisakiM/ikiw/moc.rufikiw.ne//:sptth     /flowisakim/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:sptth egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no
.nettogrof thguoht syaw ni elpoep rieht gniniatsus
.lla nihtiw yal taht regnuh dna deerg ehT
elfir citamuenp dlo na dah mrehS
,noitagimuF eht retfA
.rehtob neve ot deveiler oot saw regdab eht tub ,seye sih sdrawot demaerts dna
.tuhs leehw gnikcol eht gniworht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.epoh tsal ’srovivrus eht emaceb seitic dnuorgrednu dna syawbus ,sretlehs bmob
sa nwonk emaceb sihT
,dlrow eht fo snoiger detullop erom eht ssorca erehpsomta fo sreyal eht ssorca detautculf smrots hcuS
renibarak tleb sih pans ot erac doog gnikat
.noitazilivic no llot sti gnikat saw ti deined eb regnol on dluoc ti dna
,dedeen ti taht ecaep eht evah yllanif dluoc yteicoS
,retteb semuf suonosiop dna skael ria tceted dluoc yeht ,sesnes etuca erom rieht htiW
seloh dna sreknub eht fo tuo pets ot redro ni dnA
.rewop gnizies detrats suoitibma eht
.ssecorp cirabosi kciuq a ni
?elpmaxe rieht wollof t’ndluow tfarcreniM rehto eht taht yas ot saw ohw
,nees eb ot srenim namuh yna t’nsaw erehT
neeb ecno dah tahw tuB
tub nrecnoc rof esuac a saw noitullop ria ,sraey roF
.sknaht a tuo dekaorc eh dna
.dnuora degar mrots eht sa draeh ylerab smaercs rieht
,krow ot gnisufer
,slatem yliramirp ,slairetam detcartxe eht ,erehT
htrae eht yb demusnoc eb ot saw noitavlas ylno s’enoyreve deziroeht ohw spuorg gniraef-dog erew erehT
.snoitcaf gnirraw eht devres taht
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.t’nsaw dna deifitsuj saw esuac hcihw wenk eno on
.sevac ekil tuo-dewolloh erew hcihw srebmahc eht nihtiw deziralop secruoser dedeen-hcum
.srotcod ycnaf eht fo tnemtaert eht ot roirefni saw werbemoh dias ohw esoht editeb eow dnA
eht dna hctocs ehT  .lavivrus dna raw fo enihcam taerg eht fo trap a saw mrehS
.stfahsknarc dna sraeg fo spmup derewop-citamuenp dna sretlif citylatac ot yaw evag smetsys CAVH
,tseb erew ega latigid-erp eht fo syaw dlo eht
,sretrauq sih ot rood thgitria eht ot txen ksam sih deppord mrehS
,deMraB eht fo stcefferetfa eht morf gnippird erew seson riehT
,srebmahc citylatac eht fo seitiralop laitnereffid eht ot derehda
.metsys gnikcol lacinahcem eht otni edoc sih dehcnup regdab eht
,tnurg a sa hcum os tuohtiW
amiL dezilaer regdab eht
stisoped larenim eht no dekrow srenim rehto eht dna eh sa kcurts dah mrots neddus rehtonA
.rednetrab eht sdrawot dezad-flah gnirutseg ,lootsrab a otno flesmih deknolp mrehS
.liaverp noitazilaicremmoc did noitcurtsed fo tsdim eht ni nevE
eht gninim rof nopu dedneped llits erew klof-renim lanoitidart ehT
.nur gninim a ni tsap gnilias erew yeht egnar niatnuom a no tliub
,edisni dereggats mrehS
.ssol tnacifingis a deredisnoc ton erew sevil rieht dna
,pu ti kcab ot sepoh dna sesimorp nwo rieht htiw hcae ,gnigreme snoitcaf ynam os htiw tub
# ?sdoom elkcif ,wen s’erutan fo esuac eht saw flesti dniknamuh nehw ,yllaer ,emalb ot evah yeht did esle ohw tuB
,nwod lairetam war fo reilppus rojam eno htiW
.sdeen lacidem rieht lla rof skcauq dna nemrab no deiler suht ecafrus detullop eht nopu dekrow dna devil ohw sredispoT reroop eht fo tsoM
,devlossid eson dna taorht ,sgnul sih ni stnanimatnoc eht sa gniggag ,deMraB
,nihtiw rewoc noitazilivic s’dlrow eht fo tsal eht
thgin dna yad thguof erew taht sraW
,tenalPruF yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
snigeb noituloveR ehT
.seiceps rehto yna naht elbaulav erom era sevil rieht taht feileb rieht htiw ton
.noitisopmoc latem eht wonk neve t’ndid
.sniatnuom pota erehpsomta eht ni hgih tliub
.sreknub eht fo erutcurtsarfni yratinas dna gnihtaerb eht riaper ot desu raber dna gnipip eht
?tlover ro noitcnuflaM
,skrowlatem amakaY eht fo ytiroirp a t’nsaw rab sih fo ytirup ria eht tub
,metsys taht fo trap a saw eh dnA
,seitic gnitaolf s’namuH eht dnepsus ot desu ygolonhcet eht no desab erew hcihw
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
ria eht gniyfirup
,emoh sih desuoh taht
,ylkeew a noos erew sniar lacimehc dna snoitautculf rehtaew
eznorb tnatsiser-noisorroc elihw
.ti desuac evah dluoc stnevlos cinagro rehto ynam os ,neht tuB