gnillortnoc ,dias mulleK ”,anhsiM“
balance of bitter and oaken flavours.
him with her staff, settling
closed, nearly catching her arm.
It jerked, a pair of vines sweeping
fo egde eht ta detlah yeht tub ,pu
around Mishna as she stepped
009,45:90:00 >-- 017,15:90:00
ehs sa efink tleb reh dehtaehsnu ehS
,ssarg-egdim fo samora yksuM
078,91:60:00 >-- 016,81:60:00
in unison, each finding a break
.tnemgdelwonkca ni gum reh desiar anhsiM
011,80:30:00 >-- 030,50:30:00
center, largely ignoring the vines,
”!eciwt em llet ot evah t’noD“
fo reirrab niht eht detrap anhsiM
otni nwod gnikool ,dehgis raguoc ehT
tuoba laiceps os s’tahW
“Can’t you just… I dunno,
revetahw ro ,yballul a ti gnis
Mishna glared back at her companions.
sell two of the pods.
Mishna scowled at them.
944,65:30:00 >-- 060,55:30:00
012,84:60:00 >-- 048,34:60:00
.derettups nomyS ”!?aeT“
I can’t wait to try it!”
?dnatsrednu yeht t’ndiD
strike true now that he was no
greenery, she was at the height of
026,44:20:00 >-- 928,34:20:00
Someone behind her sneezed.
.niaga dias nomyS ”,aeT“
Kellum had his head in his hands,
gnikahs sredluohs s’gats eht
097,82:00:00 >-- 073,42:00:00
on her clothing, thank you!
971,73:20:00 >-- 031,63:20:00
gniyrt ,deknay rewolf suorovinrac ehT
companion asked in a hushed tone.
325,01:01:00 >-- 092,70:01:00
leaped away as the pistil snapped
gnimmuh reh no peed knard anhsiM
“Sorry,” said Kellum, the muscular
.gnilffins dna eson sih gnidloh gats
.snoinapmoc reh fo serats suoludercni
know.” Symon winked at the stag.
around the skullsmasher vines and
.ffo meht gnikohc ,meht gnilgnarts
doof tnalp emaceb ylraen eW“
er’uoY :0002 toB-ikahK
020,23:70:00 >-- 085,92:70:00
The stag flailed with his blade
sa tuc ot elbanu ,liava on ot
He tugged on the sleeves of his shirt,
thguac dah hcihw fael a ta gnikcip
pods and stuffing them into her pouch.
052,24:50:00 >-- 030,83:50:00
,nellaf dah mulleK—egar fo wolleb A
to have an invigorating quality to
eht ni gnikat ,desuap ehS ”…taht ti
007,84:00:00 >-- 008,54:00:00
940,31:70:00 >-- 052,90:70:00
drawn in from the surrounding foliage
show wherever you get your podcasts.
016,84:11:00 >-- 982,14:11:00
070,95:40:00 >-- 021,55:40:00
009,02:90:00 >-- 028,71:90:00
.skrow ti woh ton s’tahT“
018,31:80:00 >-- 091,21:80:00
derepsihw dna seye sih desolc nomyS
076,80:70:00 >-- 095,60:70:00
by her now humming hortimancy aura.
won gnirpsllew gninoegrub eht no gniwarD
086,42:11:00 >-- 087,12:11:00
But the real value is the brew.
.dnuorg eht ot mih raeb dna sbmil
017,82:70:00 >-- 929,62:70:00
which made tentative swipes at her before
gnilbuoder daetsni dna ,kcab gnikrej
Fleshy petals shook, tremors designed
dna yerp yrawnu nwod kconk ot
“Quiet!
longer being dragged by the ankles.
Still, she needed to be quick.
.hserf ti dedeen uoy dias reven uoY“
sih ,deirc mulleK ”!ereh pleh elttil A“
“Gods below, that’s a big word for you!”
one vine and deflecting another, but
972,14:11:00 >-- 948,83:11:00
.ni su llif ot emiT
,dereviuq rewolf evissam ehT
particular—a bright grin before
.dias mulleK ”?od uoy si ti
petals, slashing towards the two men.
”.llems taht tuoba gnihtemoS“
093,20:60:00 >-- 071,85:50:00
”!og ot emiT
like that, shirtless save for the
935,32:50:00 >-- 032,02:50:00
.gnireviuq sreltna ,rethgual htiw
.noitcifnaf dna acitore fo esod ytfeh
014,04:30:00 >-- 992,73:30:00
958,85:01:00 >-- 046,55:01:00
“Not in your lifetime, kitten.”
“Just keep it busy, alright?
fluffy Canadian canine who writes
“Oh?
Mishna lifted the herbal mix to
.delahni dna ,ti dessik ,spil reh
They should fetch a fair price!
And you two are its favourite food.”
.elims gninniw a meht dehsalf ehS
“I’m almost convinced she means it.”
eb d’yeht dna ,riaf saw riaF
”?tahW“
“Thanks.
“There you are,” she whispered.
It had reacted to the injury,
a tsniaga slativ sti gnidnefed
065,10:40:00 >-- 093,75:30:00
,hcrot delio na ekil pu til nomyS
lareves ni dehsilbup krow dah sah eH
.ffuc desahc-daerht-revlis eht no
Symon feigned a pout, then picked
.anhsiM detsaot dna gum nwo sih pu
017,81:80:00 >-- 995,41:80:00
speed, oversized stalks wrapping
the drinks tonight.”
tneipas a dellac ton s’tI
077,93:80:00 >-- 044,53:80:00
“Incorrigible more like.”
revo teprac gnitivni ,ygnops a gnimrof
Care to prove it?”
gniregnadne tuohtiw dneirf sih ot dluoc
thick vines were only singed.
”?thgirla ,netae teg yllautca t’nod tsuJ“
919,63:10:00 >-- 096,43:10:00
958,24:20:00 >-- 969,04:20:00
075,75:70:00 >-- 050,45:70:00
945,74:20:00 >-- 037,44:20:00
for the carnivorous flower.
.ydal tnalp ,thgirlA“
“I think she likes you,” Kellum
.gum sih pu dekcip eh sa dias
011,04:40:00 >-- 059,53:40:00
for shaking her horns at him.
eht dna ,laem ysae na otni ti nrut
I owe you one.”
He shrugged, winking with a
.gnihctiwt liat sih ,nirg ykeehc
snellop delgnim eht ,noitcetorp reh
already more were grabbing at him,
s’gats eht dnuora lioc ot gniyrt
She took a moment to wipe the foam
.gniylper erofeb draeb reh morf
llew yrev ton s’ti os ,thgirlA“
958,22:40:00 >-- 039,71:40:00
morf detfird amora gnirulla ,teews A
071,70:00:00 >-- 093,30:00:00
will I get what I need?”
childhood friend turned adventuring
sword-belt, with almost two yards
.ydaer eht ta dleh leets gnimaelg fo
it and forcing it to recoil.
doof gnisnes ,dekauq stnemalif yniT
078,53:30:00 >-- 014,43:30:00
!hcraeser lacinatob tnatropmi saw sihT
He struggled to his feet, and Mishna
.yb nar ehs sa mra sih debbarg
.mulleK morf tuo gnignir yrc elttab
***
You’ll wake it up early!”
006,42:60:00 >-- 095,02:60:00
onto the skullsmasher’s petals.
dashing off to her next customers.
.retnec evitsegid sti fo shtped
.deen I tahw toG“
.srerutnevda wollef reh no tluassa rieht
971,71:90:00 >-- 066,51:90:00
008,40:20:00 >-- 056,10:20:00
.drawni mih deggard rewolf eht
so it’s beyond rare, and is supposed
the thick tentacle, singing
081,73:01:00 >-- 038,33:01:00
sknaht pu desolc dah tuc s’gats ehT
“Yes,” Symon agreed, “And
”.aet eb lliw meht fo enon
046,45:01:00 >-- 040,35:01:00
“You can make it up to me tonight,
eh sa esolc sa tpek nomyS ”.ffuts toh
Beautiful.
012,35:70:00 >-- 050,25:70:00
It won’t take long.”
974,91:50:00 >-- 036,71:50:00
The boys were doing their job
.tnialpmoc tuohtiw ton fi ,llew
,emit siht mulleK ”?tahw ehT“
.ecnahc a toN
its seeds, or to eat.
.tceted ylurt t’ndluoc ti taerht
091,32:20:00 >-- 923,12:20:00
desserdrevo dah raguoc eht ,lausu sA
Khaki-Bot 2000 (2): “A
oneR enacrA yb ”werB suolireP
a wide variety of spec fic short
a htiw gnola ,seirots mrof gnol dna
dluow uoy gniyas uoy ,wwA“
web at thevoice.dog, or find the
“So heartfelt,” Symon said.
revelling in the dying rays of sunlight.
her strength, but she’d prepared this
.ksat siht rof yllaiceps xim ralucitrap
in the bushes and pushing through
gnitalulu na ,gniraelc eht otni
if you’re getting turned into plant soup.”
Thank you for listening
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
yrd tsuj uoy t’nod ,sediseB