?earesset eht fo sroloc ehT
yrautcnas ro enirhs eht ni
ylnialp skaeps esorp nialp taht hturt nialp eht
,erusserp rednu stnetnoc
,revo ssorc sgniht ynam oS
si dlrow eht taht oS
?srettel delewej eht rO
hsurb erofeb gnitsaf dna reyarp fo skeew ehT
.yrellag yrruFoS sih no sa llew sa
,gninoitulove eht suht oS
?noci eht ekam olah eht seod dnA
,gnitnuah ekil-animil ni sa
.murtceps otni nekorb si yranib redneg eht suht oS
.noitinifed yna ni yrteop rof kool ton dluow I
,tcefrep seirogetac oT
?dehsimelbnu doow nednil ehT
ssalg deniats ro
sdeen tsum gnikniht erehw thguoht fo sloohcs era erehT
yojne esaelP  .remrahC eniuqE eht
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf
stnemetats 'ylno dna fi' yb detcessid
,scitengam niht ekil krow
,yvi eht pu gnidloh morf
floWcaM boR yb meop a
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
,rekciht ecirht nworg sbmil kao ekiL
?etalap htiw teem yam
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,”noitinifeD citeoP A“
,floWcaM boR yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT
,muitaloS eraM fo retirw-oc
.snoisnelced raelc latsyrc ot dna
,gniraeb-llab tsal yreve htiw raeg gnirettilg yreve gningilA
nwohs gnileef fo htped ekiL
,rehtona ot erehps eno morF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,esrev eerf ni neve roF
.ssenyrd yranoitcid ni
tniartsnoc hturt fo ytisned eht ni tuB
tnemenorhtne ni ti si rO
ciasom ro gnitniap tahT
,elttob ados detanobrac ekiL  ,sesopmi mrof fo
.ti niatnoc ot troffe eht yb tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
seigolohtna ni dnif nac uoy seirots esohw dna ,levoN lausiV a
,detnevni ev'ew yxodohtro ylno eht ton era eseht tuB
.nekcihc dekculp yb dednuofnoc
,rehposolihp roop eht suht oS
,regnuh dna evol dna erif hguorht
.noci ciasom a ot
”noitinifeD citeoP A“ saw sihT      ?noci na semoceb
etirw ton seod erutan rehtom dnA
.redrob eht fo suoicsnocnu etiuq
.seiklaw dna enob ykaeuqs ot
seppets nezorf eht nopu flow morF
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,deifitcnas si ,dezilatsyrc sI