.elims yoc a htiw syas ttayW ”?ereht kcab em gnikop enoemos leef I oD ?hO“
”,emit txen noitnetta retteb yap ll’I .taht tuoba yrros ,hA“
ardnolA ,meht slles taht llats eht dehcaer ev’yeht emit eht yB
.dnuora kool ot imaS egaruocne ot flesmih nopu ti sekat mussopo eht
,sgninaem rieht
.demrof elzzum s’imaS elims eht rediw eht
,mih ni tseretni s’enilef eht fo eton gnikat ttayW htiW
?rethgual dna thgil dima
.kaeb reh ot stniop ardnolA
.yllautca uoy stius fo dniK“
.ni enohp dna tellaw sih speek eh erehw kcas myg ezisdim a ni sehtolc artxe eht serots eH
.era uoy ,yletinifed tsoM“ ,skrims ttayW
,ppa egassem eht gnisolc retfA
.rodnev tsal eht morf tog imaS tahw ffo wohs ot ttayW ot nruter yeht
.elihw a rof ssik eht sdloh dna enilef eht dnuora smra sih sesolcne ttayW ,detcennoc selzzum rieht htiW
?eno tsuj esoohc ot euqinu dna nuf oot lla yeht era
;gnihtyna hsur ot deen t’nod eW
.stca etirovaf sih fo eno hctac ot krap eht fo edis cisum kcoR drah eht ot oirt eht gard dluow ttayW ,egats no tes rieht sehsinif tsitra etirovaf reh ecno dnA
”!yrros m’I !yrros tihs ,hO“
.redluohs tfel sih tsniaga tser ti gnittel
,resolc nwod daeh sih snael ttayW
,gnireviuq erew spil s’imaS
…ti ton s’taht oN“ .sreffo ttayW
,revo sklaw yllausac ardnolA
.sessenrah eht fo tuo dna ni mih gnipleh elihw esolc pu ydob s’mussopo eht erimda ot ytinutroppo eht sesu eH
.reffo ot sah edirP tahw fo tser eht erolpxe ot evird eht dnif dna etardyher retteb ot elba era oirt eht ,skaerb yllanif evaw taeh eht ecnO
,sksa dna taes sih ot snruter imaS ,ezeeuqs tfos a scep htob gnivig retfA
.ssik laitnetop eht ni egludni dna etacorpicer ot drawrof nael ot enilef eht gnitpmet
,strohs niht sih revo raew ot sessenrah no-parts fo sepyt suoirav gnitset elihw ecnatsissa tuo skees ttayW nehW
.syot tluda ot semoc ti nehw ytisoiruc s’noil eht kraps thgim taht srodnev suoirav tuo tniop dluow ttayW dna ardnolA .eunev eht gnirolpxe peek ot revo ardnolA dna mih sllac ttayW sa gnol oot rof thguoht eht no llewd ot ton seirt eh ,sseldrageR
.yldemahsanu edis eninimef eht no erom gnihtemos raew ot gnitaralihxe saw tI
.enilno yub dna dnif ot drah neve erew taht emos
.ffuts ecin emos dnuof uoy ,yoB“ ,seltsihw ttayW
.ssik rehtona rof ni gninael erofeb ruf daeh etihw yffulf s’mussopo eht dniheb sdnah sih secalp yltneg imaS ,sdrow esoht retfA
.noomoom elbaffeni eht ,regguR PB yb uoy rof daer ,sivaD suiraD yb
”!duol os eb t’nod ,hhS“
”?deen uoy gnihtemoS“
,neercs enohp eht nepo sepiws dna ti seveirter eH
”.eituc ,stcnitsni ruoy gniwollof peek tsuJ“
.rehto hcae ecarbme ylthgit owt eht sa spih rewol sih dnuora kooh ti
.rac s’nosrep rehtona tsniaga pu gnisserp kcab s’enilef eht gnivah
.pu daeh sih stlit imaS
.pleh ot sreetnulov ylregae imaS
.daeh sih stlit imaS ”?yhw ,erahsedir a tsuJ“ .sksa ttayW
.tuo emoc ot sdneirf enilno dnuofwen sih fo htob morf gnicnivnoc fo tol a nekat dah ylsuoiverp ti
.tnorf eht raen s’ti ,niatnuof eht ta su teem tsuj
.enihs seye s’imaS
.ypareht tnemecalper enomroH“
.erugif rednels sih rof eb dluow ezis reporp eht tahw aedi on
,gnireffus dna raef ni edam erew seirevocsid esoht fo ynam woh dna fo hcum woh gniwonk
,smelborp yna erew ereht fi em tsurT“
,oN“ ”?hcum oot ti saW
.kcab stxet ttayW ”!nosrep ni ssa elbaroda ruoy ees yllanif ot tiaw t’naC
”edirP ta edirP A“ saw sihT
,tnemom a rof spots ttayW
.xim eht ni der fo tib elttil a ebyaM
.epahs s’rehto hcae htiw railimaf emoceb ot ecnahc eht gnitteg
.meht neewteb sesolc ecnatsid eht sa ecaf sih tsniaga hsurb htaerb mraw s’ttayW leef dluoc eH
”,elpuoc a uoy tops nac ew erus m’I
,erofeb enoyna rof sgnileef fo sepyt eseht dah reven imaS
,regnad ni regnol on si imaS hguoht nevE
,gnissecorp rof aera snoissimda eht otni cilbup lareneg eht swollof eh sA
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,sgnignoleb s’noil eht otno sdloh ardnolA elihW
,hgis yvaeh a sesaeler imaS
,roF .noitarbelec yb
fo allerbmu eht rednu gnihtyna dna gnihtyreve
,daeha sdray wef A .selkcuhc ttayW
!edisni ydaerla era I dna ttayW“ ,stxet ardnolA
.tnemeticxe eht ni tuo gnizzirf morf ti tneverp ot nwod enam sih no ruf eht stap eH
,strohs gninnur thgit emos ,sedahsnus fo riap a
tnemom eht ni sdneirf sih fo htob morf sesiarp eht gniyojne rof selttes eh ,won rof tuB
”?mih rof ylrig oot tib a era setsat ym fi tahw …tuB“
”.rof kool ot stnemerusaem tahw wonk t’nod I tub dliub ralimis a evah ot mees eW ?ezis thgir eht dnif em pleh osla uoy dluoc
.dneirf sih esaet yltbus ot nalp a smrof eh
,kaerb moortser kciuq a retfa meht htiw pu sehctac ttayW ecnO
.nruter ni ezeeuqs eltneg a reh gnivig ,emit siht guh eht stpecca ylidaer imaS
.eno gnisahcrup elbatrofmoc ton er’uoy fi yadot eno yub ot deen t’nod uoY
…tsuJ .doog er’uoy
.hcum taht lla erac t’ndluow eH“
”,eno gnorw eht gniyub yb bmud leef annaw t’nod I dnA
.hcum taht lla dnim ot mees t’nseod tub
eb ot evah t’nseod ti ,lleW“
si ro odibil wol a dah eh hguoht sa ton s’tI
”!tcefrep yletulosba sdnuoS“
,syot tluda suoirav
;aedi retteb a evah dluow ehs gnipoH
.mih erofeb mussopo llat dna evissam eht ta pu skool dna snrut eh
”?meht hcuot I fi dniM
,ecnatsid eht otni traped ti sehctaw dna rac eht stixe eh ecnO
”?ekat yrevocer eht did gnol woH“
”?I dluoc ,uoy ot etuc taht eb t’nac I“
,cisum fo serneg elpitlum ot retac taht segats lareves erew erehT
,sdnaw ,srotarbiv ,sno-parts ,sdoohpup
”.uoy htiw yad eht gnidneps emit taerg a dah tsuJ
.noitnetta s’imaS sehctac taht eno si ereht
.mih serussa imaS
,seye sih gnirucsbo sgnab etihw gnol htiW
.yawa thgir gnilf nuf a tsuj
”!esruoc fO“ ,sdon ardnolA
,niht os ydaerla strohs s’noil eht htiW
.seye lufepoh htiw pu skool imaS
…ot evol I“ .sreffo ttayW
.spil rieht tcennoc ot avilas fo gnirts llams a gniwolla
,gnikniht evisicedni fo setunim ytriht retfA
.emit txen rof esahcrup eht ffo stup imaS
,pohs pu gnisolc erew srodnev eht fo ynam elihW
”!uoy wohs em tel ereh ,ysae s’tahT“
”,htiw senomroh ruo etaluger dna tnemelppus ot esu ew tahw s’tI
”,kcehc ot truh t’now ,no oG !os wonk I“
,seohs gninnur elbatrofmoc sih si tfel s’taht llA .slaitnesse erab sih ot nwod si eh litnu stnap dna tekcaj sih ffo gnippirts strats imaS
.em ot nosrep tselooc eht tub gnihton neeb ev’uoY
.yoj htiw noom eht revo llaf imaS edam hsurc sih morf tnemilpmoc ehT
.sezis raewrednu dna sgnikcots fo smret ni rof kool ot tahw tuoba noitanalpxe deliated dna trohs a evig ot seirt ardnolA
.cilbup eritne eht rof swohs elpitlum no gnittup ,stca cisum eht yb deipucco erew segats niam
.secnavda s’noil eht tsiser t’nseod eh hguoht
.elcsum mrif erup si htaenrednu
.oga sraey wef a enod meht daH
.gniklaw thgil emos retfa laem ytraeh a rof tuo slworg hcamots siH
.raew ot uoy tcepxe elpoep rehto tahw revo gniraew elbatrofmoc tlef uoy gnihtemos esohc uoy fi desserpmi erom eb dluow eh kniht I
.pu mih stfil smra yffulf etihw gnorts fo riap a sa ria eht ni pu detsioh steg ydob s’noil ehT
,sgnab s’mussopo eht htaenrednu taht ees dluoc imaS .skrims ttayW ”,noitautis ykcits
.edud ,thgirla s’tI“
.sksa imaS ”?TRH“
.ecnartne s’krap eht nroda taht sgalf edirP suoirav eht gnirimda ,wodniw eht tuo skool imaS
.triks inim etihw a dna ,gnikcots ,seitnap fo sriap roloc tnereffid tuo skcip eH
.MA00:1 tsap ydaerla s’ti taht sezilaer dna enohp sih skcehc imaS
,ytic yldneirf reeuq dna nepo yllauxes yrev a ni nevE
,ssik eht morf kcab sllup ttayW ,yllautnevE
.epyt suoetruoc eht eb ot seirt syawla eh
”?tif eht s’woH !uoy ta kool ,hO“
.wonk uoy tel ev’dluow I
.doof slles taht draytruoc egral eht ot yaw rieht sekam puorg eht
.hctorc s’imaS tsniaga pu ttub sih egdun yllufyalp dluow ttayW
,sgalf fo egnar eht ot semoc ti nehw ecivon a etiuq si eh ,llitS
”!yddub ,ay ees ot ytinutroppo eht ssim t’ndluoC
.skrims ttayW ”!sesucxe ,sesucxE“
,lauxesnaP spahrep ,lauxesiB s’eh ebyam
.gniyrt ni mrah on s’ereht tub ,yas t’naC“
,selggig ardnolA .sksa imaS
.trihs reh htaenrednu sdnah reh htiw stsaerb llams reh secnuob yllufyalp ardnolA
.dekrap ehs aera eht nwod worran dna yrt ot nottub mrala eht gnikcilc dna syek rac reh tuo gnignirb ,drawrof seunitnoc ardnolA ”.doog er’ew ,haeY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.hsuh a htiw syas imaS
.thgin eht tuohguorht strecnoc evil eht syojne eh sa eunev eht fo sedis owt eht neewteb setanretla eh ,imaS rof dnA
,ylfeirb spots tuo gnikcab revird klE ehT
”!uoy ekil yllaer I ,dnA
.ecalp thgir eht ta sevirra noil eht ,hguone eruS
.tol gnikrap eerf tseraen eht sdrawot skcolb lareves gnisrevart yb rac reh ot ardnolA gniklaw si ssenisub fo redro tsrif riehT
.tey tuo flesruoy derugif ylluf t’nevah llits uoy fi yako s’tI“
,kcab gniworg morf ruf sih stneverp eussit racs eht hguoht nevE
.dniheb morf pu gnimoc ylesolc spetstoof decap tsaf fo sdnuos eht pu skcip eh
,keehc s’enilef eht skcil yllufyalp ttayW .seifiralc imaS
,strecnoc evil gnidnetta dna gnicnad eunitnoc ot sevol eh sa hcum sA
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”?gnol rof gnitiaw owt uoy peek t’ndid I epoh I“
tuo gnikcab ylwols erofeb erutseg dnah dna kool citegolopa na gnisserpxe
.etihw dna kcalb eb ot sdnet ti
,yawa llup t’ndid ttayW ,revewoH
”,gniht siht htiw yawyna ssik doog a evig nac I ekil ton s’tI !em etib ,hO“
,taes sih ni kcab syal ttayW
.ytinummoc TBGL eht fo sdeen eht ot cificeps secivres ot gniretac shtoob dna
,scep sih sexelf yllufyalp dna tuo mih gnikcehc noil rellams eht sehctac ttayW
.edud ,yadot looc os gnieb rof sknaht ,netsil ,yeH …thgir ,hA“ ,dloh sih sesaeler ylneddus imaS
.noitnetta sih sbarg taht gnihtyna t’nsi ereht
dluow …wonk t’nod I“ ,nwod
,raewrednu eninimef retfa-thguos drah slles taht htoob a si tI
,imaS tsniaga pu sesserp yltneg mussopo ehT .ssik eht nepeed
daeh sih sdon imaS .segaruocne ttayW
”.hctac eht etiuq er’uoY
”?taht ekil gnihtemos gniraew yllis kool I
”?mussopo emosdnah eht sserpmi ot gniyrt ,hO“
deugitaf erom ylgnisaercni emoceb ydaerla sah ydob sih
,tif tcefrep a erew yeht sa gnieeS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knaht dna ,edirP yppaH
,teg ot tahw fo smret nI
.eb ot sevlesruo derevocsid evah ew ohw fo noitarbelec a esruoc fo si edirP
?ytitnedi fo smret ni flesmih no stcelfer siht woh saw noitazilaer siht gnirud imaS selzzup taht gniht ylno ehT
”!tnorf eht raen eb ll’eW
.yawaevig daed a si egamulp der dna ,kcalb ,wolley yliramirp reh sa ardnolA naht rehto on si ttayW dniheb morf tuo gnikeep namow retrohs ehT
,gnineve ylrae eht ni pohs pu esolc srodnev eht fo tsom erofeb hguohT
,tnemom feirb a rof yawa ezag reh snrut yllausac ehs ecnO
.trapa sehcni s’elzzum rieht htiw enilef eht sdrawot resolc snael yltneg ecaf s’mussopo ehT
,meht ta deivel gnieb snoitseuq cisab eht etipseD
.esnes sekam ,hA“ .seifiralc ttayW
,snoisses tahc eciov gnimag ruo ni snart erew uoy em llet t’ndid uoy fo htob eht fI
.daeherof sih kcep yltneg ot drawrof snael ttayW
,god.ecioveht ta
ot reh rof stiaw dna ardnolA ot revo skool eH
.thgis fo tuo saw bac eht
,cisum eht ot gnola ebiv ot elba erew ymmaS dna ttayW .dworc eht gnoma gnicnad elihw drow rof drow stih pop nitaL tsetal eht ot gnola gnignis ,krap eht fo edis cisum nitaL eht ot oirt eht ekat dluow ardnolA .dnetta ot wohs tahw fo smret ni ttayW dna ardnolA neewteb dellup gnitteg emit sih fo tsom tneps imaS
.htiw seifitnedi yllanosrep eh tahw dna
,wap dnah a htiw nihc sih dezarg yltneg ttayW
,yamsid s’imaS ot hguohT
,mih ot tuo ti stniop ehs nehW
”edirP ta edirP A“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.ytaews elttil a era smlap ym fi ti pleh t’naC
.kcab gnidnopser erofeb sthguoht sih srehtag mussopo eht ,sdrow sih ni gnikat retfa hguohT
,erolpxe ot tneve eht fo hcum llits si ereht sa gnieeS
,sdon imaS ,thguoht emos lasoporp eht gnivig retfA
eht fo tsoM .gnorts no seog llits tneve edirP eht
ardnolA ,kcul siht ot dnA .etunim eht yb
.sredluohs s’noil eht dnuora mra eno sparw eh sa syas ttayW
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa reeuq kcalb a ,sivaD suiraD yb
,mih sguh ylthgit imaS
!laturb gnikcuf saw yrevocer eht ,htnom a tsomlA“
,ekil uoy gnihtemos ees uoy fI“
.dnim sih fo kcab eht ni gniretsef ylwols dna gnidiser morf desopxe gnieb fo raef llams eht detneverp ti naem t’ndid tahT
.revo sessap evaw taeh dlim a sa oirt eht skooc nus remmus eht
.sevirra noos llafthgin sa
,noil eht ot snrut neht ttayW .emoh kcab gnivird dna tuo gnikcab ylwols erofeb sevaw tsal wef a sevig ehS
!detcepxe I naht retteb ,gnizama s’tI“
.tsehc ralucsum sih fo edisrednu eht gnola hcterts sracs eht sa yregrus pot s’mussopo eht fo tnetxe eht ees ot elba si imaS
,krap eht fo saera rehto erolpxe dluoc imaS erofeb hguohT
.orb ,doog lla s’tI“ .sksa imaS
,hcuot eht ot mraw semoceb ecaf s’imaS
.esaet tsuj naht erom od nac I ,lrig hO“
,ti swonk eh erofeB
,netsil ot gnilliw dna rehto hcae htiw tsenoh era ew sa gnol oS
,sekil yob taht gniht eno s’ereht fi ,netsiL“
.llew sa ecarbme yldneirf a imaS evig ot revo gniog erofeb mih ta sevaw yllausac naiva ehT
?thgirla gnihtyrevE“
”,yltrohs ni eb lliw ,puY“
”,taht ekil pu teg a ni etuc yllaer kool dluow uoy kniht I ,yltsenoh dnA
,ebyam lauxesimeD
,dias ardnolA ,redluohs s’noil eht gnittap yltfoS .stimda imaS
.looc ytterp kool yeht ,haeY“
.tuo sllac eciov eninimef A
hguohT .guhraeb eht morf tuoba hsarht liat dna sgel sih htiw dnuora smriuqs imaS
tlef eh ,rorrim a ni flesmih ta kool ot elba gnieb tuohtiw nevE
,esidnahcrem edirP
,sthgilhself ,sgnir kcoc ,sgulp ttub ,sdaeb lanA
”.laed gib on s’tI .sllab ruoy gnitsub tsuj m’I“
,dnah sih dleh llits noinapmoc enilef eht yhw noitseuq ot mees t’ndid ttayW
,sgalf fo noitceles eht sesworb imaS sA
.htiw yfitnedi I yltcaxe
.gniklaw trats-owt eht sa s’ttayW otno sgnilc llits wap dnah-thgir sih
”.gnigrahc trats ot evah ll’I
.tuo sllac ttayW ”!imaS“
I sseug I …naem I hO“ ,sehsulb imaS
?won gnineppah s’ti yhw srednow eh os
.dneirf enilucsam sih ta kool esolc-pu na steg imaS ecno setapissid ylkciuq ti ,dnim sih sllif ecnayonna fo noitome eht erofeB .ttayW si mih erofeb nosrep eht taht noil eht ot tnerappa semoceb ylkciuq ti
”?egnahc I elihw sgab ym dloh uoy nac ,ardnolA
.deneppah tsuj tahw ni sekat eh sa ecalp ni gnireviuq
.ttayW edisgnola klaw ylesolc dluow imaS
ew od tahw ,oS“ ,sksa imaS
.yub ot eno hcihw no elttes ot gniyrt emit tluciffid a evah ot seunitnoc eh
”!neht ecnis puc ezis-lluf a deniag ydaerla ev’I dna srednow seod TRH
.noomoom elbaffeni eht
,sdon ttayW
.tnetnoc ylluf eid dluow noil eht neht ,taeper
.yaw ruoy no erew uoy erus ekam ot detnaw dna tib a gnirolpxe tsuj erew eW
,slley yldeticxe ardnolA
.rac reh edisni gnibmilc erofeb guh a sdneirf reh fo htob sevig ehs
,dooG“  .sdnopser imaS
.ni egnahc ot llats moortser cilbup tseraen eht gnidnif erofeb gab eht morf seidnu knip dna triks inim etihw eht tuo sekat imaS
…tub thgiarts morf raf m’I wonk I ,naem I
”?niaga uoy ssik nac I fi thgirla ti si neht …yakO“
.ma I ohw tuo gnirugif elbuort evah llits I
,striksinim ,sgnikcots
,tahc puorg eht nI
.moor mrod egelloc sih ni yalpsid eno gnitteg tuoba suoiruc neeb syawla sah noil ehT .smialcxe imaS
thgir sih otno llup ylhguor ttayW sleef eh ,tcaer ot emit sah enilef eht erofeB
.tcejbus eht hcaorb ot tsrif eht si ardnolA
,nips elttil a seod imaS
,emit emas eht ta srevocsid enoyreve ton tuB
”!ardnolA ,pleh ruoy lla rof niaga sknahT
.rehtona eno otno gnilc niks evitisnes eht gnittel dna pu spil sih gniward
.tol gnikrap eht gnivael dna
.ekat ro evig sraey ruof tuobA“ ,seunitnoc ehS
sah eh sa llet ot tluciffid emaceb ti ,revewoH
.erusnu llits si imaS
”!thgin tsrif ruoy retfa latipsoh eht ni pu dne uoy tel t’nac ,retteb uoY“
,daeh sih fo kcab eht sbur imaS
?tnereffid yleritne gnihtemos ti si ro
”,pu ti peek uoy fi ereh revo ssecnirp eht morf ssik laiceps a teg neve thgiM
,htaerb sih hctac ot ssik eht morf yawa sllup imaS nehW
.tesolc eht fo tuo gnimoc ylcilbup fo raef sih sedirrevo yliraropmet nosrep ni sdneirf sih gniees fo tcepsorp ehT
,dnah eerf rehto sih htiw kcab sevaw ttayW
.gnigakcap eht nepo ot gnideen tuohtiw yltnedifnoc pohs ot elba si eh sa no tops saw noitamrofni reh ,kcul s’imaS oT
.thgis eht ta yzzuf dna mraw gnileef skeehc sih
,sdneirf sih sdrawot emac eh resolc ehT
,kcab sih pals ot dnuora snrut dna shgual ttayW
,meht fo yteirav evissam a dlos srodnev ynam sa noitces yot xes eht si pots tsrif ehT
.tnemnorivne wen sih otni gnilttes elihw ttayW morf noitceffa lacisyhp drawtuo eht gnidnim ton
yreve hcum ytterp dah taht dnats a was I
.hcuot gnihsinif eht sa triks inim etihw eht no stup neht eh
,eson knip sih hguorht degdol gnicreip mutpes a
.yad eritne eht tuohguorht gnitrilf eht ni dednah yvaeh repus gnieb tuohtiw esaet yltbus dluow ttayW woh dnA .gniraebrevo ton
.esaet a hcus syawla s’eH
!ti htrow yletinifed saw ti tuB
os siht lla ot wen yrev llits m’I wonk tsuj
.pu wohs ot noitavitom gnicitne na noil eht edivorp noitacol elbissecca ylisae dna gnimit tneinevnoc ehT
.meht fo eno esahcrup ot noitaripsni fo gnilkni na kraps syot etaidemmi eht fo enon taht tsuj ,xes ni detseretninu
,ardnolA ot revo skool eH
.yaw taht ti peek ot snalp eh dnA
.guh edis mrif a noil eht sevig ardnolA
.sdnoces wef tsrif eht tuohguorht suovren dna ,ykahs
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.etag tnorf eht hguorht sessap eh sa nwod etar traeh sih gnipeek no sucof ot seirt eh ,won roF
.teef rieht no yad lla gnidneps retfa ylralimis gnileef erew ttayW dna
.sessenrah no-parts derised eht yub ot rodnev eht ot revo gniog erofeb kniw tfos a sevig ttayW .sih fo seye kcalb lufituaeb esoht fo espmilg a teg ot elba si eh
.ton ro tif guns a eb dluow yeht fi ees ot sgel sih no meht gnicalp yb stnemerusaem eht llabeye ot seirt eH
”!tem reve ev’I nosrep elbaroda tsom eht era uoY
!sic erew uoy demussa ev’dluow I
.serutaef enilucsam s’mussopo eht fo erom gnirimda
”?thgirla syug uoY“
,ereh uoy tog I ecnis ,lleW …eniF“
”?seibab esehT“ .revo skool ttayW ”?rof slrig ruoy dah uoy evah gnol woh ,ardnolA ,yeH
.lortnoc kcab sekat erutan suoicsnoc-fles s’imaS ,yawa gnivlossid tnemom gniteelf eht htiw hguohT
”!nam gib thgir taht t’niA
gnittel ,sgel s’enilef eht fo eno pu stfil smra gnorts s’ttayW
.eciov reh ni prihc a htiw syas ardnolA
,yot evitartenep a tuo flesreh skcip ardnolA
”.uoy dnuora erom pu flesym nepo ot yppah m’I neht
,trihs-t knup cinoci na gnipper dna
,klaw rieht gnirud emit fo sdoirep gnol rof mih ta gnirats flesmih dnif netfo dluow eH
”.taht ekil dluow I kniht I ,haeY“
,segdun yltneg ttayW
.uoy rof elbatrofmoc dna larutan sleef tahw od
.srodnev suoirav yb dedivorp erew syot tluda
,won dna ereh thgir fo smret ni tuB
.sevitcepsrep wen ecneirepxe ot sredaer emirp ot yaw a sa gnitirw sesu ohw
.yalpsid no dah relles eht galf snart tsegral eht tuo syub ttayW elihw ,galf ecA dna citnamorA dezisdim a pu flesreh skcip ydaerla ardnolA
.dnah s’ttayW otno gnidloh llits elihw hgis yvaeh a tuo stel imaS
.gnihtemos raew dluoc
.eelg htiw esira ruf enam llams eht sekam ecnedifnoc fo tsoob wen a
,hgis tnatculer a tuo tel imaS
”?uoy od ,si roloc etirovaf s’ttayW tahw wonk ot neppah t’ndluow uoy …mu ,haeY“
.strohs dna partskcoj sih ffo sekat yletaciled eH
.stcejorp gnitirw erutuf rof
.tuo eugnot sih skcits ttayW
.ynapmoc ruoy yojne tsuj I
,regguR PB yb daeR
.segaruocne ardnolA
yrevocsid fles rof ecalp a eb osla tsum ti os dna
.lla dna ygnilc elttil a sa ffo emac I fi yrroS
.drah mussopo eht no gnihsurc saw eh taht tcaf eht stpecca yltnatculer eh ,yaw a nI
.ttayW ,uoy ot taht od annaw reven dluow I dnA
.tnemssarrabme ni pu gnisnet ecaf sih htiw ttayW morf yawa gnikool flesmih sdnif noil ehT
,noitalpmetnoc ni srehtaef nihc reh sekorts ardnolA ”.tcepxe ot tahw aedi on evah I os eno ot gniog emit tsrif ym s’tI ?edirP rof ereh dnuora od
rettiwt no mih wollof nac uoY.sevitcepsrep
,reve edirP tsrif sih si siht taht gnieB
,niatnuof eht ta sevirra imaS ecnO
.noil eht ot gnitacixotni erew seidnac teews dna ,sdoof deirf ,skcans detlas ,staem fo llems yrovas ehT
”?ereh teg ot erahsedir a ekat ro yb esolc krap uoy did ,oS“
,evitcartta yrev ttayW gnidnif rof yaG eh sI
”.ay no tif ll’ti fi tuo dnif dna yrt
.sih ot ralimis yrev si dliub dna thgieh reh taht gniciton
,tnemevap talf eht otno nwod tes nehw
.elpoep rehto truh yllatnedicca thgim I taht era sgnileef eseht tahw yltcaxe wonk t’nod I fi deirrow tsuj m’I
tahw wonk t’nod I tsuj s’ti
.sdneirf owt sih tops ot gnipoh sgnidnuorrus sih snacs eh
”?thgirla ,tnemgduj nwo ruoy tsurt tsuJ
.gnidnetta s’eh swonk krow ro loohcs rof stcaretni ylraluger eh elpoep ron srebmem ylimaf sih fo enoN
dlof srae s’imaS
”!yaw eht daeL !em rof skroW“
.gniog noitasrevnoc eht gnipeek yb detcartsid oot teg ot ton seirt eh hguohT
”?eye ruoy sehctac tahw ees dna tuo ti kcehc annaW .epyt
,scep sih fo pot no syal taht taf fo reyal yhsiuqs niht yrev a si ereht elihW
?tnaw uoy fi sgalf edirP emos rof dnuora pohs dluoc ew …lleW“
,egassem reh retfA
,syob eht ta kcab daeh reh skcoc ardnolA
.egde no sevren s’imaS sah yad eht tuohguorht pu dliub dna gnisaet eht llA
.s’ttayW otno spil sih tnalp ot drawrof gninael erofeb htaerb peed a sekat noil eht ,seot sih fo spit eht no gnitteG
.ssik etanoissap eht tuohguorht serutaef s’rehto hcae yduts yletamitni ot nraey seidob riehT
.raf uoy teg lliw pu su gnirettuB“
,yawa skcab yletaidemmi imaS
,sehtolc s’rehto hcae htaenrednu ekans swap rieht fo htoB
.sdnopser ardnolA
”?uoy ot doog dnuos taht fo yna seoD
.noitpircsed rieht gnihctam enoyna eb ot mees t’ndid ereht tub
”?tnaw uoy fi ,emit rehtona pu eno kcip syawla nac eW
”!teews os s’taht ,wA“ .selims imaS
”.neve ,taerG .doog kool uoY
”!taerg kool owt uoy ,lleW
elamef dna elam rof xesinu erew taht spot knat dna
.trihs-t dednarb gnimag etirovaf sih dna
.ydob tes-yvaeh sih setadommocca retteb taht sessenrah no-parts ytilauq-hgih emos rof dnuora spohs ttayW elihw
.tsehc ralucsum s’ttayW tsniaga hsurb ylthgil wap dnah sih gnittel ,sdon imaS
,meht ta erats ot eunitnoc seye s’noil ehT
.serutaef s’mussopo eht gnirimda ,ylthgirb gniremmihs erew seye s’noil ehT
”,setsat ruoy stius taht gnihtemos teg ,oS
.eivom a dna tuo ekat emos rof revo uoy evah ot nwod llits m’I
.yldetcepxenu tuo gnikcab detrats meht fo owt eht fo tnorf ni rac eht nehw noitnetta yap t’ndid imaS ,enilef eht gnitcartsid skool s’ttayW htiW
”?ees uoy tahw ekiL ?huh dar ytterP“
.dnim yna mih yap t’noD“
.krap cilbup a fo ecnartne eht ot pu sllup rac erahs edir detner llams ehT sivaD suiraD yb
,esahcrup eht gnikam retfA
.noissimda eht morf deretsulf ylthgils semoceb ecaf s’ttayW ,ecno roF
,mussopo citsicuel a dna tebrab naivureP naiva na rof tuokool eht no eb ot wenk ydaerla eH
,tahW“ .stimda imaS
,sdneirf sih fo htob woh gniciton
retfa ylno desserdnu eh erus edam imaS
.eert ydahs a rednu hcneb krap a no gnilttes erofeb slaem derreferp rieht tuo kcip sdneirf sih fo htob gnittel ,hcnul rieht rof gniyap no stsisni ttayW
.noihsaf s’elpoep rehto ot semoc ti nehw tnelavibma ytterp s’eh tuB
”?yadot revo gnimoc llits uoy era dna
”?uoy ta tuo gnipmuj gnihtynA“
ro gnol oot rof regnil t’noD“
,sdneirf sih sdrawot sdaeh dna llats moorhtab eht morf tuo spets eh nehw dnA
tey elbahcaorppa sa ffo semoc eh yaw ehT
.yadot ti teg ot hsur on yletulosba s’erehT
.raer ylepahs dna htgnel sih fo pot no ylguns tis dna taoc ruf nat sih dnuora mrofnoc yltcefrep ti gnittel ,tsrif raewrednu knip eht no sedils ylhtooms neht eH
.si ssa s’ttayW tfos dna daorb woh tsuj ecneirepxe yltbus ot elba si imaS
,haeY“ ,sksa ttayW
.mih gnigassem erew
.ecalp tsrif eht ni tneve eht gnidnetta htiw hguorht og mih pleh ot tsoob ecnedifnoc eltbus a sa sevres osla tI .gnola emoc ot mih ecnivnoc ot dah yeht hcum woh fo rednimer a sa sevres tnemmoc s’ttayW
,ttayW dna ardnolA
.eglub suoivbo na gnitaerc
,strohs sih tsniaga ylbatrofmocnu gnisserp kcid mrif sih leef dluoc noil eht ,elihwnaeM
,ni semihc ttayW ,yldeticxe sdon ardnolA sA
,tcennoc spil rieht erofeb hguohT
.tiftuo wen sih ni etelpmoc
no yalp ot tnemom eht ezilatrommi dna etaluspacne ot yaw a saw ereht ylno fI
,edahs eht htaenrednu gnittis etipseD
ttayW did evoorg dna mhtyhr larutan nwo sih s’dnif imaS ecnO
,rac dekrap reh sdnif yllautneve ardnolA nehW
”?os kniht uoY“ .selims ttayW
,ssecorp lavomer eno gniruD
”?tnaw uoy fi ,em htiw thgin eht dneps ot ecalp ym ot revo uoy gnirb ot nwod m’I ,esac taht ni ,looc hO“
.level repeed a no ti tuoba gniriuqni rof bmud leef imaS edam reven yeht
,spil s’ttayW sepacse elkcuhc llams A
dna nus eht morf pu gninrub si eh hguoht sa sleef ttayW
edam eb dluoc yeht erehw dlrow a rof daetsni hsiw ton dluow ohw
”,kcip ot eno hcihw wonk t’nod tsuj I …yas ot drah s’tI“ .sksa ardnolA
.suoivbo ssel lasuora sih ekam ot ti stfihs dna strohs sih ni htgnel eht sbarg ylkciuq imaS
,ssik eht tuohguorht lacidohtem dna wols si ttayW
.kcas myg sih edisni gnitarbiv enohp sih leef dluoc noil eht
,sdneirf sih fo htob morf noitacifiralc htiw nevE
,trihs sih ffo ekat ot sediced
.ttayW morf tohsrae fo tuo eb dluow yeht taht os revo naiva eht sllac imaS
”,pu ezeerf ton ot tseb ym yrt ll’I
)seirotsd2( ta egap yrrufoS sih dna goDdliWD2@
.tuo sllac eciov peed A ”!ay dnuoF“
”!uoy ees yllanif ot doog ,yeH“
.sgnikcots etihw dna knip depirts eht rof seog yletaidemmi dna
.yaw eht fo tuo mih evom ot dnah
.detardyh seednetta eht peek ot sretaw elttob dellihc eci paehc gnilles ylidaer erew srezinagro ehT
.yltcaxe ma I tahw wonk t’nod I
.erutxet htooms tahwemos a deniater sah llits ti
.noitcerid sih ni ecnalg ton
,dael eht sekat ardnolA elihW
.tnaw uoy fi wap ym fo og tel nac uoY“
.meht fo htob eht dnoyeb raf ti gniyojne saw ardnolA hcum woh raelc emaceb ti tub
”edirP ta edirP A“   yojne esaelP
a ni pu dne dna yad doog a no em hctac neve thgim uoy ,swonk ohW
.eert ydahs eht htaenrednu gnittis elihw elkcuhc a erahs oirt ehT
.ttayW dniheb morf seohce eciov tnereffid a ,dneirf sih ta gnikwag eunitnoc dluoc imaS erofeb hguohT
,selggig ardnolA
”?thginot taht fo yna raew annog er’uoy knihT
.daeha raf oot gniyarts morf ttayW gnippots ,htoob eht fo tnorf ni gnidnats imaS eciton ot tsrif eht si ardnolA .seidob
.meht fo hcae dniheb gninaem eht dna galf elgnis yreve tahw nwod kaerb ot hguone ecin erew ttayW dna
.yadot tcefrep erew uoy ,wan tuB
.noitasnes wen eht ot tsujda spil sih evah dna smra sih ni xaler noil eht gnittel