.hguone esolc ylbaborp saw siht os dna naeco eht nees reven d’eh tub ,naeco eht t’nsaw ti wenk eH
,yhtrow saw debircsed yeht tahW .on tub
nialpxe ot evah ll’uoy
,retteb hcum taht yllaer
?reyarp ni gnirevesrep tub mih ot tfel saw tahw tub
droL eht fo gnimoc eht fo romur a draeh sah dnim ym ,oS  .kcaP eht ni
.dedrawer neeb sah dna
,srehtaef sti deffulf ,edartsulab elbram eht no dednal worc a ",yrrow
.yrgnuh og meht tel t’ndiD
?niaga morf draeh eb ot reven ylekiL ?ereh deralloc dna thguac mih evael ot ylno
?draeh ton evah uoy eb ti naC
.esoh erif a erofeb wons gnitlem ekil
.snoino dliw erew
,ti rof deksa ew taht ton ’ycerces ot thgir‘ eht tog ev’ew syas
,rodo yksum ,yrageniv lufrewop eht neeb evah dluohs gninraw tsrif ehT
nisuoc ym taht dna
”!flow a sa nees eb flesmih tel eH“
?siht ot mih gnirb ecnedivorp dluow yhW
.htworgrednu eht morf degreme dah ohw sevlow eht fo eno dniheb edor eH
,rehtegot gnieb etipsed enola hcae ,snamuh desufnoc fo dworc a ton
!ti ni .D.I ruoy sah taht“
”.lagelli ton oslA“
.elop htron eht dnuora selcric tniaf otni deraems lla dna ,sroloc ynam oot
.ti gnidnuorrus sedannoloc etihw-wons eht dna
detartnecnoc dna waj sih dehcnelc eH
,segrahc yna evah t’nod uoy fi si ti tahw s’taht esuaC ?noitcudba siht htiw deecorp uoy tel dluohs I nosaer rehto yna tog uoY
.ti ot desu teg uoY“
woh tuo dnif annog er’uoy won os“
.ylhsipeehs ,detcejbo dah flow gib eht ”!pup ,truh tog ydoboN“ ’!niaga taht ekil gnihtyna‘
.gninraw a htiw ffo mih tel ot saw
,erew yeht sa ton meht ees flesmih edam eh nehw edirts sih tih eh tub
...“ llems sa hcum sa mih detresed dah gniraeh tub mih ot gnikaeps saw enoemos erawa saw eH
.rehtie oga tnemom a ereht neeb t’ndah
.gninetaerht tuohtiw netaerht dluoc flow gib eht woh evisserpmI
.mih evas ot ,ylraelc ,tnes neeb dah ohw esoht dna mih neewteb gnidnats saw tnega llat ehT
.tesnus cirtcele tnenamrep a ekil
,dneirf ,ti ekat em ekam uoy fi dnA
!kcap eht fo trap saw
gnol a yltnerappa saw tahw hsuh ot gniw a desiar worc ehT ”-dna
.ecnetnes-dim deppots eH
.rehcnual eht nwod tes tnega gnireens eht
.rotom s’ekib sih sa eton emas eht saw lworg s’flow gib ehT ”?ti gniwolb
tnapucco eht ot yas ot tliub
.esahc tsenrae evig ot
”.seye ruoy neewteb
.txen mih dedeen ecnedivorp erehw ees ot emiT
?tser ot ecalp emos deen uoY .yawynA
taht deen ot gniog er’uoY
”.ereh sevlesmeht gnidnif ta hguone tuo dekaerf teg yehT“
,floW eht ot gnidroccA lepsoG eht morf gnidaeR A yojne esaelP
.flow rellams eht deffocs
,retlaf ton did tnega eht ,tiderc sih ot ”,oS“ ”!tohs taht ot
.thgirlA“ .dehgis seliM
?notnedmaC ni dessarah uoy namow roop tahT
,dereens tnega gnireens eht ”:tuobawoH“
,srats fo lluf dna
?noitisopxE lainnetneC dna riaF s’dlroW 3981 eht fo draeh uoY“
?ti retne ot yaw eht dnif ylno dluoc uoy fi
.htron dettort eh sa dluoc eh sa god yarts a ekil hcum sa kool ot deirt dna
".ereh uoy wollof t'nac yehT"
emoh s’kcap ym ot
,suovren rof edam seitic gib taht
revetahw ni efas dna teiuq deyats tsuj adluoc uoY“
dah yeht ,neht ,yhw deksa tsuj eh os ,sruoted elbanimretni erew meht fo tsom detcepsus eh dna ereh no gniog snoitseuq fo tol a erew erehT ".ni meht tel ew sselnu" ,retnalp depahs-nru eht morf gnillips yvi eht pu debmilc ohw nooccar eht dedda
.tlahpsa eht tih ti nehw nups daeh siH
,dah eh epahs ekilflow tsom eht ni
.yawa klaw ot evah t’nod I tuB“
yhtapme suoetip ot yaw evag yrrow deltratS
”.tnega ,snoitpo ruoy redisnoc uoy oS“
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daeR
,niav ni neeb evah ton krow ym tel
.dnim on ti diap yeht
”?thgir ,enoyreve gnillet llits er’eW“
?secaf ruo wohs nac kcap ym fo enon oS ’?sevlowerew suoregnad‘ tuoba
.dluoc eh sa ,yllufetarg dna
trats ot gninetaerht‘ htiw derapmoc stun gnihtyna llac d’I fi“ ,dias naD ”,onnud I“ ”?thgir ,stun stnerap ym evird annog s’eH ?thgir ,yzarc saw“
?ti saw ,won thgir gnineppah gniht lausunu tsom eht yldrah saw taht neht tub
,tnega eht ni demihc
,worromot llits si taht tuB
t’nsaw adanaC ,EFAS ton ,llew
,emoclew ,yhtrow si hcihw luos ym fo lla
ot gniksa otni deklat uoy dneirf ruoY“
ytiucipsnocni htiw denrecnoc oot eb dluow stnega eht gniyarp
yad txen eht tuo mih tel spoc eht nehw dna
”,ssenisub ruoy fo enon s’tahT“
.ekal eht dna meht neewteb mih dah yehT
,gnidaelp ot tog ti resolc eht reikaeuqs tog eciov s’nooccar eht
.em pord uoy ebyaM
uaerub RUOY hguoht nevE
”.leehw eht teg ot hguone teg t’ndid ew ,haeY“
yrots s'yadot dna
,erofeb elcycrotom a no neeb reven d’eH
.ezis elbaicerppa yna fo ytic a ni toof tes d’eh ecnis sraey ,llew ,neeb dah tI
demuserp d’eh ecnagorra sih ni tuB
.tsenrae ni nur eht no saw eh ogacihC dehcaer eh emit eht yB
”.gninraw eno ylno teg lliw uoY“
”.nam elttil ,ssim uoy epoh retteb uoY“
,oot stnemetats rieht tog ev’ew ,haeY
.krap eht dehcaer dah eh emit eht yb egde no ylbaresim saw eh dna t’nsaw ti dna t’ndluow tI
,stnega eht nwod doots dah ohw flow gib eht dias
ym ot uoy ekat ot smotsuc fo edis rehto eht no gnitiaw si naI
,yltsenoh ,tcepxe ot thgir yna dah eh naht rehtraf tog eH
,ned a dellac uoy eloh yhtlif
.yks eht saw ereht neht dnA
.spup ylenol ekil mih ta pu dekool htob yehT
.frut rieht morf raf ton er’ew ,eguoR niaN ehT
,hO .tsaerb s’tserof krad looc eht no serohs etihw rof denraey evah smaerd yM
,leehw sirref eguh a ,tsew eht oT
,mih pots ot yrt t’ndid tub ,seye rieht dellor yehT
,nagihciM ot egdirb gnol eht ssorca kcab daeh ot nrut meht dehctaw eH
.llik ot deliaf dna deirt tsuj uoy flowerew eno evah tsuj t’now uoy wonk uoy
?gnihcaorppa enigne eno naht erom ereht saw ,tiaw
.retaw eht ssorca sedannoloc etihw eht ta yldetcejed derats nooccar ehT
!devas eb tey dluoc gnihtyrevE .devlos eb tey dluoc gnihtyrevE
.sevlow eht tsuj ton dnA
,nug dedaol a nwod gnirats ton fi sa deunitnoc flow gib eht
ot dedeen eh fi nur ot erehw aedi on dah eh tnaem taht sdworc dna sllems detcepxenu dna sesion duol
,eb d’eh ,redrob naidanaC eht ekam dluoc eh fI
esoht niatrec saw eH
,suonimul demees yeht elap os ,etihw gnimaelG
retfA“ .ffo rentrap sih tuc ot deliaf dna deirt tnega llat eht
.esuap gnol a saw erehT
.dewollof gnieb saw eh erus saw eh eekuawliM tsap detriks eh emit eht yb tuB
”?raw a trats annog s’ohw woN“ .deerga nitraM
.euc no ylraelc ,deltsur daor eht fo edis rehtie ot segdeh ehT
!mih etib ot flowerew a sa gnisop poc revocrednu na deksA ?denrut teg
.nug a nward dah tnega gnireens ehT
.drawemoh denrut yehT
eelilaG dellac ecalp a fo noitnem a draeh evah yam uoY
.wef eht rof htlaew fo niatnuom a dliub ot yawa sevil rieht evals ot tsom ecrof t’nseod kcap A
,denrut teg ot gniyrt rof detserra tog sitruC yug siht woh tuoba yltsom“
.mih koot ,ytinamuh desrucca fo siloporcen siht ni toof tes d’eh ecnis daehrevo gnirevoh ,cinap dliW
,llew ,fo hcum thguac evah ton thgim I
,nar eh ,denrut eH
.ytinamuh ruoy dna eman ruoy yawa werht uoY
,salob dethgiew eht saw tog eh gninraw lautca tsrif eht tnaem hcihW
t’ndluow I“ ”.noitanalpxe na tnaw I ekil leef I taht
?aes ymrots dna tfos eht yb seilil sti fo ytuaeb eht dnA
!ot tuoba erew yeht meht gninraw saw I“
.ssenisub nwo ruoy dednim dna
.snaem taht tahw tuo dnif annog er’uoy won
”?annog s’ohw ,rehtohcae tcetorp t’nod sevlow fI
’egac a ni tsaeb a era uoy ,renosirp a ton era uoy‘
.erofeb tnemom a ereht neeb t’ndah taht
”!sthgir evah t’nod yeht yaw rehtiE .sretsnom ro slamina rehtie er’yehT“
morf gniworg dnA
ycilop uaerub taht derebmemer stnega eht tniop siht ta saw tI
,noisulcnoc tpurba sti yb desufnoc erom dna nomres sih yb desufnoc srekoolno neewteb
s’teL .gnorw ton er’uoY
,yalp riaf ylno si tuobanrut eugra dluow ohw ,floWcaM boR yb
,srae detniop dekcirp neht
,gnimoc si ti ,gnimoc sih dnA
!meht hcaer nac tnega ro poc on erehw tub ,ytic namuh eht fo traeh eht ni ,su ekil esohT
,duol tuo dda t’ndid eh ,sa gnol sA
”,tnega ,lataf ton s’tI
”?llet ll’yeht ohw swonk ohw dnA
.ykcutneK ni nilbog yrevE
.etinotpyrk ton s’tI
,rehtorb ,reverof tiaw ton od ew tahT
”?emoh teg ew nehw ti tuoba klat
”.elbuort edam ev’t’ndluohS
”-namuhartxE fo uaeruB eht fo
,ngisdaor a dniheb morf tuo deppets ohw
hguone esolc ti gniod dna
.yllatnemirepxe mih deffins ,elkna sih ot pu
”!skeew rof mih esahc su edam eH“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m'I
”.meht llet ot yawa klaw d’uoy tnedifnoc yllaer mees uoY“
,sucof ot tluciffid ti edam enigne gnihcaorppa na fo dnuos ehT -evigrof
renroc eht dnuora tsuj erew
,uoy knaht meht dlot eH
.gniod er’uoy tahw wonk t’nod uoY
”?siht gniod eb ot tnaw uoy erus uoY“
.hteet sih derab
.nosiop ton s’revliS
.flesti llac ot gniog t’nsaw kcaP taerG ehT
,namuh tsom sih ta
.aiulella ,yrolg yrolG
?ytnuoC nonreV ni morf depacse uoy ffirehs ehT
”.hguoht ,me ot klat yllausu t’nod eW“
,ereh esle eno on saw erehT
thgir ti tup ot deen tsuj I“
,tser fo lufsnaeco taht ni
,ni elbmuts me tel ,kcarc a rood eht nepo tsuJ .enoemos gnissarah ro gnisahc era spoc eht nehw ekiL“
?thgir ,soediv esoht elpoep gniwohs llits er’eW“
.goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil er'uoY
!flesruoy ecifircas ot gniyrt ton er’uoy dneterp t’noD
?ereh saw ,ksa ot dah eh ,yltcaxe ,tahw oS
,dniheb tfel dah nam egnarts eht tellaw eht htiw delddif nayR
,puorg htuoy a eganam ot deifilauq ton er’uoy yhw si“
,ytic eht fo noziroh laicifitra eht dniheb ylwols dellor
-dna ,seert yrrehc wol fo sknab owt neewteb dekcud eh oS
tog eW“
,tellaw sih evig ot deirt eh mohw ot ,dniheb neddir d’eh flow eht dias ”!oN“
flow eht sa ereh emoc d’eh fi ,no ksam namuh sih dah eh lufetarg yletaidemmi saw eH
”.ot pu neeb ev’uoy tahw wonk ew os
,enola saw eh fi tuB
",ereh ni teg nac ydoboN"
seert eht devom dniw ehT
.ekatsim a neeb dah tnega ’reildneirf‘ eht sa eno siht fo gniknihT
,meht dlot eh ,eno evah ot sih tey erew ti fi tub
...ruoy ot em llac dna ,tser ot sfeirg ym lla yal lwoh yht teL
.dluoc yeht sa esolc sa ylraelc ,pu dellup dah selcycrotom eerhT
?tuoba deklat gnieb saw ssergorp sih
”,stseug lanoisacco teg ew ,naem I“ ?tahw ,tiaW
tnega gnireens a yb derif
.syad tsom ,hguoht ,ti ees nac eW“
.snoino dliw fo etsat eht ,desimorp eh ,dnim t’ndid eH
,ecno ta nosrep eno naht erom ot gnikaeps deirt erofeb reven d’eh dezilaer eH
skcaP lla fo rehtaF hO
,sag rof deppots yeht nehw ,dias gerG ”,yug tahT“
.tselb eb eman s’worromot yam
.emoh sih eb ton dluoc siht
?detnaw uoy tahw siht t’nsI
,kcab ofni eht taeper ot detnesnoc eH ”?taht tog uoY
,flow gniklat-tsaf eht denialpxe
.yaw rehtie ecnereffid a edam ti ekil toN
,slamina owt taht laerrus elttil a saw tI
elbarenluvni ton m’I snaem tsuj ti“ ,deffuh eh
”!dab os ton s’tI“ ’.retfihsepahs a‘
,meht wollof ot ezag maeb thgildaeh a denrut
.tuo dekconk neeb evah ylbaborp d’eh
swollag taht no yrolg si erehT
raw a gnitrats htrow saw
.tnega ,senohp tog ev’eW
od reven eh dednamed dna flow gib eht ot thgiarts enog dah rehto ehT
.goD fo ecioV eht ot
”!ytefas nwo rieht rof tsuJ“
,klawedis eht ni kcarc yreve morf ,trid fo hctap yreve
,swal yna nekorb t’nsah ohw nam a gnitserra yllagelli er’uoy ekil“
,obmika llits smra ,flow gib eht delworg
,llew yrev wenk uoy eno saw ti sselnu ,thguat neeb d’eH
tuo DI sih gnikat fo tniop nrobbuts a edam tub
”!pu denrut s’retfihsepahs rehtona emit tsrif eht si siht dna sraey derdnuh a neeb s’ti tub“
,elzzum deroloc-thgin a desiar
sih naht namuh erom dednuos
,noitavlas sih ot tuo neddir dah
repeed reverof knis ot
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.snoino fo llems eht saw mih tih taht gniht tsrif ehT
tnargav elgnis a yhw
.dias tnega llat ehT
?yloh gnihtemos fo trap erew yeht taht ,deksa eh ,meht dlot reve enoyna dah dnA
htap levarg a otno delbmuts-
,yhtrownu si hcihw lla
,gnillac yloh a dah llits eh tuB
saw eh taht mih ot derrucco reven dah ti ,timda ot dah eH
ytirohtua lanoisivorp rednu“ ,kcab emac ti sa gniyas saw tnega rehto eht
.taorht namuh a yb edam neeb evah t’ndluoc taht enO
”!?kcuf eht tahw ereh ni skcub dnasuoht a ekil
”.sdik erew ew nehw saw ti ekil ton s’uaeruB eht taht wonk ot sdeen ,flow enol yreve ,kcap yreve
.sllac gnikam detrats ew os“
”!mih etib ot enoemos dnuof dna kcab thgir tnew
,nisnocsiW ni poc yreve ot gniworc yad elohw a dneps uoy
!swal yna nekorb t’ndah ohw
”!t’nod uoy wonk lla ew hcihw
.gnihtoos yletaidemmi neeb dah—
.sehsub eht drawot deddon flow gib ehT ”.ma I“
”,thgis no sevlowerew gnitserra erew spoc lacol eht lla taht ffo deppit
”.tnedicni retfa tnedicni gnisuac
,eriw detsiwt dna leets erab ,esoht fo skcab eht wonk t’ndid eh taht dluow—
mih rof ecalp a eb dluoc ereht dlot neeb dah
enoemos revo gniod neeb ev’t’ndluohs uoy hcihw dna“
deldnurt nooccar ehT ”,tol a siht od eW“ .hgual hsrah elgnis a dekaorc worc ehT ”!ot su tnaw t’ndid stnega esoht esuaC“ ?ni mih tel
”,evitpursid s’yug siht ,ttum ,kooL“
.klofhtoM fo snoitagergnoc owt tsaeL .sanorolL saL
,drawrof denael flow gib ehT
,dne s’yenruoj ot efas nees
,em ot elbaliava llits
.htiw smret gnikaeps no ton er’ew kniht uoy
.aes eht fo dnuos eht emac hcihw hguorht edacra na
.snoitalupop namuhartxe yna dnim reven
,kcaP taerG eht tub kcap yna
”,llet annog er’ew ekiL“
.krap eht fo dne rehto eht ta erew stnega eht nehw mih denraw dah worc ehT
,deen retaerg ni neeb I evah reven—
,ylkciuq sa ogacihC tfel dah eh 14 yawhgih edisgnola dlrow eht otni kcab gnigreme nO
,ecnedivorp fi dnA
”,revo lla skcap rehto morf uoy tuoba draeH
.tner yap meht ekam t’ndiD
”.tuoba gniklat saw eh gniht atros eht ekil dednuos taht ,haeY“
dlrow suorednow erom
”.ttum ,uoy rof ti ekam nac ew dab
.t’ndid eh ebyam tuB
.tup deyats ev’dluohs uoY“
.ste’qsaS eht llA
.oiratnO ,ekaL repilaC ni kcap ’stnerap
,dias nooccar eht ”,lleW“
.meht retfa dah eh reyarp yreve tnes dna
mih fo tnorf ni gnidnats nam gnikool-derit eht fi derednow dna ,enil smotsuc eht ni ecalp sih koot eH
noogal dicalp eht dnuora rednaw seye sih tel dna gniliar elbram eht no denael eH
.taht ot kcabemoc a dah tnega reildneirf eht ebyaM
”!resolc yna ecnavda ton oD“
.nug sih rewol ot rentrap sih llet ot mih ot rucco ot mees t’ndid llits tI
t'noD" ?mih detivni tsuj dah ohw
,sessim ti fi dnA
,saw eh sa kcisemoh sa ,saw eh sa yraew sA
.sneppah ,sneppah tahw neht dna
,ylsuoticilos swap sti depsalc nooccar ehT
.ecnelis eht yllanif dnA
.daor eht ni nwod ecaf mih tfel dna
.emit elohw siht gnidrocer neeB
.won mih revo gnidnats saw tnega llat ehT
.reverof t’nsaw ti
.dnim sih fo renroc gnisucca ,suorehcaert a derepsihw
”,selim dnasuoht owt uoy esahc su edam uoY“
,sdaor eht gnikcolb erew srac eciloP
evah niaga reven dluow eH
!sretfihsepahs rof nevah a ti ekam dluoc ew dnA“
nees eb t’ndluow ti erehw ,daor eht ffo dekrap d’yeht rac deromra eht gnirb ot enog dah rentrap gnireens siH
.stnega eht naht retteb eb ot dah ti tub
”.ssenisub ym s’ti kniht I ,haeY“
.redluohs sih no dethgila worc ehT
”,taht ekil ti tup d’I taht wonk t’nod I“
,yas enoemos ,draeh naht rehtar ,tlef eH ”!yaw siht ,yeH“
”!ecnis reve ereh gnivil neeb ev’ew dna ,gnipeek efas rof emit syawedis fo ydde elttil a ni lla ti tuP“ ”.ti elots ew oS .enod saw riaf eht nehw nwod lla ti raet annog erew yehT“
stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy syawla sA
.knuks ybraen a ylerem saw siht demussa dna
”.stellub revlis htiw nug siht dedaol I taht“
,ti dias eh nehw esnes ssel tol a edam tI“
.detcepxe evah d’eh naht reivaeh saw tI
.flowerew a emoceb ot enoyreve rof saw dlrow eht evas ot yaw eht taht drow gnidaerps
.noitcidsiruj s’uaeruB eht fo tuo eb d’eh tsael ta tub
”!elpoep etib ot dereffo s’eH“
”’!uaeruB eht htiw raw a
,daetsni daorliar a dewollof eH
.t’ndid eh ,meht tnes dah ecnedivorP ro doG dias eh fi dnatsrednu ton thgim yeht desseug eh ecniS
,flow a saw hcae morf gnitnuomsiD
,floW eht ot gnidroccA lepsoG eht morf gnidaeR A
,owt fo owt trap ,floWcaM boR yb
”?thgir ,tuoba gniklat erew uoy tahw yllacisab s’taht tub ,ereht tuo evig ot gniyrt erew uoy hceeps revetahw
.deggurhs flow gib ehT ”.yrt dluoc uoY“
,tuo ylluf saw nus eht hguoht ,thgin sa kcalB
.dennirg flow gib ehT
,raf os mih dael yhW
floWcaM boR yb
”.yrtnuoc eht ni flow yreve htiw
s’erehT“ .suoludercni dna llirhs ,dekrab eh ”!syuG !aohW .hguoht
,sthgil htiw gnirettilg
,sessob ruoy ot kcab ti ekam uoy fi ,neht dnA
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daeR
.pu kool ot dnuora detsiwt eH
,enigne gnildi fo
,egnarts yllufrewop gnihtyna
alusnineP reppU eht dna ,atosenniM
.dlrow eht ni ereht tuo
”!lortnoc redrob hguorht og uoy nehw
.teg ot ylekil reve saw eh ecneidua tsegral eht erew sdebrewolf dna ssarg eht gnoma tuoba gnillim elpoep ehT
:eb yad eno dluow yeht sa tub
.derussa I ma taht fo
.dnats tsal ym si siht ebyaM
,mih hsubma ot tnaem stnega eht ecalp eht dnuof d’yeht woh tuoba sliated eht fo tsom dessim eh taht hguone swen suoyoj saw taht dnA
.teg uoy tohs ylno eht s’ti wonk uoy ,od uoy fI“
,gninrut won neve saw sitruC
”,em ot skool ti esuaceB“
.dnesdog a ,llew ,neeb evah dluow ti flow rehto yna rof dna ,tsuj dna
,yawa ton em nrut eeht erofeb dnats ot yad ym eb siht fi dna
.su fo eno llits saw eh ,stun saw yug taht fi neve ,yawynA
daor eht no keehc sih dial
nos derovaf remrof sti
,mih part ot nwod dial ksum dirca eht raelc ot nageb dna
.eciov wen a delworg
,em ta tohs a ekat uoY“
,detsetorp seliM ”!raw a trats ot gninetaerht t’nsaw I“
.mih derongi ,suoires dna drah eciov ,newO
”.ereh snoino ekil gnitsat pu sdne gnihtyrevE“ ”.era
,yrovas ,evila ,hserF
.daor eht no tellaw eht gnivael dna
.tsew eht otni ssap taht spihs yerg mils fo demaerd sah luos yM
rehto eht no ,emod ekilhcruhc eguh a saw edis eno eht nO
.redrob naidanaC eht dna ,eiraM .etS tluaS ot
”,noitneted otni nekat gnieb...“
.detsisni worc eht
,setats evlewt ssorca su gard ot evah uoy ,on tuB
.dedragersid sksam namuh ,detfihs yltnaifed
,loof a ekil detcartsid saw eh tub ,tnecs a ksam ot ereht saw ti desseug evah dluohs eH
.srieht ekil eno erew ti taht dluow eh
”,tihs adnik sihT“ .flow fo dna
.niaga eno edir reven deen eh denrecnoc saw eh sa raf sa dna
”.esle erehwemos kool dna pu evig spoc eht llit tsuj
.demees ti ,niaga dluow dna ,did eh emahs sih ot tub
.yrellag yrruFoS sih no seirots eht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.gnimlehwrevo ylgniretaw-eye dna
,sneppah gnihton fi nevE
,tserof fo sllems eht htiw ti decalper
.tnega gnireens eht deppans
.ysae saw kcap a ot gniklat dnA .kcap a sa tub
.em redrum uoy hctaw annog si yrtnuoc eht ni flow yreve ,si ti fi tuB
,ekib sih morf yawa pets eno koot ,spih sih no stsif sih detnalp flow gib eht
”,tnega ,boj ruoy si hcihW“
,seye sih desolc eh—
.tnemec tol gnikrap eht ffo pu ti depoocs meht fo eno yllautneve dna
.yhw tuo dnif ot tnaw t’ndid eh dna
.etelpmoc saw ti ,egamirglip siht no od ot tnaem neeb dah eh revetahW
?tnemeganaM ecalupoP namuhartxE fo uaeruB eht fo daeha pets eno yats eh nac tuB
.dloc eht ni tuo srebmem sti evael t’ndid kcap a woh meht dlot eh oS
.tsrif ta drawkwa elttil a saw tI
.sgnidliub eht saw deciton eh gniht dnoces ehT
,htraeh ruoy ta sehtolc ym ,rood ruoy ta stoob ym yal yam I erehw ,esuoh yht ot dael daor ym tel—
tnenitnoc eht ssorca deyenruoj rehcaerp flowerew cirtnecce na ,emit tsaL
,rewoT leffiE eht dna ,siraP od-tuo ot detnaw yad eht ni kcab ogacihC nar ohw setangam eht ,eeS
”?ereht era uoy fo ynam woH“
.erutcel decitcarp-gnol dna
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.dias tnega gnireens eht
emit syawedis fo ydde na ni sgniht gnittup fi sa ,nooccar eht dehsinif
.draoba teg retteb
hatU ni seilimaf eripmav esohT
.gnar eciov s’tnega llat ehT
,snoitalutargnoc ,lleW
.saw eh tahw dna ohw fo tcaf cisab a tsuj
”.eergasid annog ton m’I tub“
,edir a mih nevig d’ohw rekcurt a gniksa derebmemer eh ,nees reve uoy evaH
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dnA
.elttil a tsuj ,retlaf did tnega eht woN
,lanoisuled mees thgim eH
.retnec dna tnorf tseggib eht ,tfel eht ot eno ruod dna derruf-kciht a ,thgir eht ot eno rellams A
.lufetarg eb ot ti dnatsrednu ot deen t’ndid eh tub
”,hu ,I“ ”?yrgnuh uoy erA
.ekal eht tub gnihton neeb dah tsae eht oT
erecnis nevorp si htiaf sih tub
.niaga reven meht deen dna
.stnega .M.P.E fo .B owt eht was eh
.regnad dna peels dna doof erongi uoY .yenom ruoy lla yawa evig ot yrt uoY
t’nsaw taht—ytic eht t’nsaw taht gnihtyna fo thgis ehT
”.yllausnesnoc enoemos gninrut tsniaga wal on s’erehT“
taht seciov htiw deklat llits
.did tsuj uoy gnihtemos saw
,ynam ooT .srats gnorw eht tub
.sdnah sih otni kcab decrof saw pmul rehtael deggar dna nrow ehT
,reurt ,redliw a fi sa ,nialpxe t’ndluoc uoy taht
uoy knaht ,dluoc eh sa yletilop sa
”?yats uoy gnimussA
”,tihsllub taht htiw rehtob ot deen t’nod uoy ,naM“
.daor eht revo lla daerps
.taht dna mih neewteb wohemos eb dluow ecnedivorp
,etib eht noitnem ot tuoba saw eh nehw tsuj dnA
,ylluferac os mih ediug
.niaga yaw sih no eb ot mih rof hguone raelc ot tsaoc eht rof detiaw eh elihw ,meht htiw laem a erahs ot dalg eb d’eh tuB
.nisnocsiW hguorht ,htron delf eH
seno eht er’uoy won
.secalap dedanolloc dna sedacra lufecarg gnol lla
raf t’nsaw ti ylikcuL
”.eerht evah tsuj t’now uoY
,os mih gnillet saw ohw ro ,saw ’yaw siht‘ erehw wonk t’ndid eH ”!kciuQ“
.raeh dluoc rae ro ees dluoc eye sa raf sa
.era uoy fi ,snoino ekil uoy epoh“ ,dedda worc eht
,sevlowerew elbatirri
.traeh sih fo mottob eht morf ,meht deknaht eH
,snihs sih desiurb ,selkna sih dnuora depparw taht
.mih thguac stnega eht erofeb
?yeht dluow ,ot evah t’ndluow yeht ,neht tuB
”,nam a gnitserra er’ew yas
.retaw eht fo elddim eht ni htnilp reh morf ylsuoicipsus mih dedrager eutats nedlog gniliart-eniv A
,tcA mlactnoM eht rednu yrautcnas gnimialc er’uoy yas ,flowerew a er’uoy meht lleT“
,floW eht ot gnidroccA lepsoG eht morf gnidaeR A
,eb dluoc eh naht lamina erom hcum eb ot elba erew ohw
?eeht fo emoceb lliw tahw