,nwot edisrevir llams a ni pu dnuow dah eH
,tellaw sih fo tuo drac eht dehsif eh
,ecitcarp koot tI
,pu tnew sworbeye sih
,tsae dedaeh saw niart ehT
,esidarap fo etsaterof ynit a ekiL .kcap eht fO
,tegrof ton tsum dniknam taht rebmemer I taht sgniht roF
.ssorca klaw ot yaw oN
.dworc ylenol eht gnoma stsohg fo ecnad eht ni ti tlef evah I
.rewsna ot woh nwonk evah t’ndluow eH .llew sa tsuJ
,yarp ot mih thguat dah
,kcen sih fo kcab eht ot gniod saw nus eht tahw yb desoppus eh ,tsaehtroN
,seenk sih ot despalloc
,desoppus eh ,kcap a ekam ot stros lla kooT
.sduolc eht no sniatnuom eht fo snoitcelfer ni ti nees evah I
sadacic htiw dellif ydaerla saw thgin ehT
.detcepsus t’ndaH .huH
.seninac prahs hcus htiw dedeen ybab a tahw
.gnivael saw sub eht
,ti t’nsaw ,dnalrevir eht fo traeh eht ni
noitcidsiruj eht fo tuo eb tsum eh erus saw eh nehw dna
,thgin siht ni saw esle gnihtemoS
,tnemeganaM ecalupoP namuhartxE fo uaeruB eht morf ,DI sih fo renroc mottob eht ni
.enohp eht morf gninruter nam eht dias
mih ot gnineppah saw gnihtemoS
eciov taht draeh ,srae sih ekorts wap taht tlef
,emoh tsal ta saw eh
ssom dna seert dna niar htaenrednu repeed llits dna
.mih ediseb hsart eht ni
.reverof maor ot secaps etinifni dna
,meht rednu enilosag dna latem hguone htiw od thgim elpoep fo sdnik eseht tahw etamitserednu reveN
,hguorht deppets reveN
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daeR ,owt fo owt trap
,gniog saw eh erehw dna mih neewteb erew yehT
.tnuocca on fo saw taht tub
,dnuos ro thgis detcepxenu na yb esool deltsoj
.dniheb morf mih dedrehpehs yltnelis
etib eht tuoba trap eht ot tog eh nehw dna
daeh sti gnikahs
”,skramer trams ekam t’noD“
,tnaem dah ti tahw
rekcurt eht htiw elttil a klat ot deganam eh tuB
?eh t’nsaw ,ti tsap saw eh won dnA
siht yfitset dluow eh tub
lamina gnikcinap eht no pirg a peek ot gnithgif
modllarht ni setareneged roop eseht sah taht nomed eht tuB
,namow decaf-drah A
ruoy fi ,etunim a uoy evig nac I sseug I
,peels ot mih llul yawhgih no sleehw fo muh eht tel ,snialp ot nrut edistuo tresed eht tel
.edir a thguac eh ,thgin eht dna sniatnuom eht htob fo edis rehto eht nO
,emit gnol a mih ta dekool ehS
.llew yltcefrep wenk eH
.goD fo ecioV eht ot
mih fo tnorf ni dellup dah rac s’firrehs etihw dna kcalb eht niaga teef sih ot delbmarcs d’eh emit eht yb dna
,taht seod ti uoy llet lliw yrtnuoc eht ni thgin ta klaw a rof seog ohw enoyna flesmih dlot eh dnA
denimreted ,yawa gniklaw ydaerla saw eh tuB
.sniatnuom tnatsid eht fo seenk derettahs eht dehcaer yeht litnu
.yad eno ,uoy rof kcaP taerG eht ni ecalp a s’erehT
sevlowerew ,ma’am ,reh erussa dluoc eh taht gniyas htiw
.yrellag yrruFoS sih no
?og ot eerf eh saW
.mih ot ti dnah ot tnaeM
.elbat eht ta tis ot yrt t’ndiD .olleh dias eH
.goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil er'uoY
,sey ,gnirewoprevo eb ot sa gnorts os ,floW .mih dnuora lla saw llems eht tuB
,sthgil eht morf seye sih dleihs ot dah eh dna
.taht enod d’eh emit tsrif eht eb t’ndluow ti tub ,thgin lla sniatnuom eht hguorht gniklaw naem dluow ebyam tahT
.neeb ecno d’yeht tahw t’nerew srae sih dna
namuh tub gnihtyna gnieb fo tcepsus ot esuac yna dah evah dluow ydobon
,pih reh no saw nug reh
.dluoc eh taht dnif dluow allef eht thguoht eh dias dna kcab delims eH
?enod eb ot ereht saw esle tahW
.gnirewsna regnol on ,nellus ylrettib
.ecaep eb d’ereht
.gnihtyna ro snatas ro snomed yna htiw od ot gnihton dnA .laer erew
,dehctam erow nemow eht sgnir eht deciton eH
.denrut eb ot ksa t’ndid sitruC .t’ndid eh os
,egnarts lufrewop gnihtyna nees reve eh dah dnA
’!reganam ruoy
.aedi dab a t’nsaw taht tuB
”!od yeht kniht meht sekam
miH tpecca enoyreve taht
,tcatnoc eye edam eh oS
.rood taht nepo dehsup reveN
.rac dezisrevo reh otni kcab deltsub ehs esuaceb
eht fo llac eht raeh did reven sitruC fi ,ton fI
.gnidliub eht fo renroc kcirb eht dnuora
.retaw yddum eht llems dluoc eh litnu ,seert eht otni
.flow eht fo dellems yeht yltsom tub
yhtrow dnuof eb em tel eeht ot emoc ot ruoh ym eb siht fi ro ,skcaP llA fo rehtaF draugefas ym eb
tsehc gnivaeh sih
.senob sih ot nwod mih wenk dog sih ,sediseb dna
.ediba stnias fo senob eht erehw tsevrah ythgim a lleterof I
.mih ot dellac reve ydobon esuaceb eb t’ndluow ti tsael ta ,kcap
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
,taes eht ni kcab dexaler dna
,floWcaM boR yb
sdniw tnereffid fo leef eht ,sllems eht ,sthgis ehT
.elbissop sa ylkciuq sa evael dna tuo llup ot tnaw ot demees tsuj ehs tuB
,tsew erom elim a ro tsae erom elim a naht rehtar
krap VR eht evael niaga reven dluow taht reliart pu taeb eht ni nam dlo eht nehw ,syad dlo eht morf rebmemer dluoc eh ekil
.levarg yddum eht ni
,lleW .noitats dnuohyerg a saw egde eht tA
”.yawhgih a no ciffart gnitcurtsbo rof“ ,dias ehs
.rettiuq a tey ton si ti tuB ,tihs fo lluf s’taht dlrow a fo yraew suordnow si luos yM
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daeR floWcaM boR yb
,dluoc eh sa tsaf sa gniklaw detrats ,nwod daeh sih tup eH
ylimaf eno eb dluow dnikflow lla nehw
.elgna siht morf mih ees dluoc esle ydobon ,lleh eht tahW
elbatrofmoc saw taes regnessap kcurt imes ehT
.derob elttil a neve dna
.eb ot dedeen eh erehw mih gnirb ot ecnedivorp detsurt eH .enif saw tahT
,sgel owt no ,flow eht ta
,sitruC dias ”,pleW“
.tey regnol elttil a tsal ll’I
,tsap pihw snwot sionillI tnatsid fo sthgil eht dehctaw dna
.drac xedni na fo ezis eht tuoba ,koob cimoc elttil a ekil dekool tI
.dias eh ,no sserP
.tesnus erom eno tsael ta ees lliw seye eniM
,suoregnad ,evila gnihtemos
,enod stfihs ym gnitteg
.gnorw gnihton ,delims eh ,oN
elbatirahcnu neeb ev’dluow ti tuB .hgual a neeb evah thgim taht taorht sih fo kcab eht ni esion llams a edam eh dna ,yltfed
.rewsna ot rehtob t’ndid eh os
derednow dna ,deliaw ti sa hteet elttil eht ta ylesolc yrev dekool yeht sselnu
,aremac a gniraew t’nsaw ehs
ehT nahT REGNORTS‘
,thgilb eht erofeb syad dlo eht ni smle neeb evah dluow taht seert yldnips fo wor a dna hsif a fo eutats ssalgrebif giB
?tniop a evorp ro eelf ro egarof naht rehtar ,ti fo yoj
flesmih detnetnoc eH
,dessap sraet eht ecnO
,revo uoy wercs t’ndid taht ,detsal taht ,diap taht sboj ehT
si taht ,efil siht ni—kcap eht ni ecalp sih dnif ot tnaem saw eh fI .ko saw tahT
,renroc yreve dnuora dlrow suordnow erom ,reurt ,redliw a erew ereht fi sa tlef ro
,gninrom siht pooc rieht morf nekcihc a elots taht tsaeb eht detroper evah eno on tel esaelp—
,nur ro edih deen erom on eh erehw
.egamirglip siht no dedeennu
”.naem I tahw wonk uoy fi ,emit ot emit morf ssendnik a owt ro rekihhctih a od I fi tuo dnif ynapmoc eht nittel ton dna
sokcis cinatas eseht esiwrehto esuaceb
”.DI ruoy tegrof t’noD“ .llew sa wenk eH
foor racxob eht no tas eh sa tuB
.uoy gnipleh eno eht m’I ,reh dlot eh ,ma’am oN
,scificeps eht raeh ot deen t’ndid eh tuB
.lufepoh erom ylbaredisnoc
.tfel sih no erehwemoS
”.em ta tohs a gnikat tsael ta tuohtiw yaw ruoy no eb uoy tel annog t’nia ecneicsnoc
ti dessaP .wollip a sa gnihtolc sih fo eldnub eht htiw foor racxob eht no kcab sih yal eh sa ti fo gnileef eht ot no dleh eH
.mih ot emac erom gnihtemos
,roivaS lanosreP rieht sa
.rekcurt eht dlot eh oS
.sdne yenruoj eht woh tuo dnif ot
?reciffo ,wal eht tsniaga taht sI
!flow a otni snrut reve yllautca ydobon os
,noitseuq eht detaepeR
?eugra ot eh saw ohw dna
suoicsnoc ylluf deniamer eH
,ylerus ,ereht segdirb eb d’ereht dna esolc saw ti rehtie tub ,raf woh erus t’nsaw eH
,nosaer a dah ecnedivorp neht
,edir eht gnidnes rof sknaht dedda htiw ,ecnedivorp ot kcap eht ot gnimoc rof-depoh-eb-ot sih fo dna
,knab levarg eht pu dehsad eH
.gnitfihs morf peek ot nwod pmalc ot evah mih edam ,pots mih edam ti tub
,revir eht morf dimuh dna looc ,htuos eht morf yrd dna mraw—
.deneppah reven dah
,tesnus nmutua gnitsalreve na rednu
,floW eht ot gnidroccA lepsoG eht morf gnidaeR A
,enohp eht ot gninetsil tsuj
.pu gnuh neeb evah neve thgim llac eht elbissoP
.edit gnisir a sgnirb ti dna
,eman namuh sih morf eerf mih tes dah
,htron ecaf sih denrut dna
”!llew sa gninrom siht wodniw nekorb a detroper hcruhC pihswolleF tsriF
ll’uoy swen tnatropmi tsom eht
.ydaerla yrots eht fo snoitairav ynam oot wenk eh
.meht htiw epoh koot dna
deklats dna denrut
”?retsim ,ereh gnorw gnihtemoS .olleh hU“
ti drawot pets a koot eh nehw tuB
.ylnialp ti llems dluoc eH
droL eht fo gnimoc eht fo yrolg eht nees evah seye eniM
.spetstoof on draeh eH .enif saw tahT
?lanosrep oot ti saw rO
emehpsalb t’ntsum
,reh dniheB .mih ton ,reh
.eb ot deen yeht erehw kcap ruoy teg ot meht esU
.dnim on ti diap eh dna sseltneler dna sselicrem saw daehrevo nus ehT
.ot desoppus saw eh  naem t’ndid ti od dluoc eh esuac tsuj tuB
,yhw ,tiurf raeb dluow taht ytisoiruc fo dees a eb dluow noitasrevnoc siht neht—
,ngised tcefrep s’doG htiw erefretni t’nac yeht esruoc fo tub ,yzarc
emit txen ni enuT
?rehtegot kcap a dloh ot tfel ereht saw tahw
.oooon hO ”!yporhtnacyl ro
mih ot derrucco tI
!ereh attuo uoy tsac I dna nataS fo
.seye gniyrp ynam oot daH
,rehto eht fo tnorf ni toof eno
.dluoc flow a tbuod oN
dna thgit pu meht dellor
“ dias ehs erehw trap eht ot ydaerla saw dna
.yloh dna ,yldlrowrehto
.adaveN fo ssenredliw noen eht ecnis gniod neeb d’eh ekil tsuJ
?tfel evah reve ot
,eenk taht no daeh s’flow sih dial ,erif taht yb riahc taht ot enog tsap eht ni reve dah eh fI
,koot ti tahw s’tahT
mih tsniaga gnihsurb
.tsrif egdirb rehtona ot emoc d’eh dna
,meht raeh dluoc ydobon erehw nwo sih htiw emit ni yltcefrep dednal sllaftoof s’dog os
,gnirats erew elpoep dezilaer evah tsum namow eht won yb dnA
yrots s'yadot dnA
.gnihtyna dias t’ndah eh fi sa ,detaeper ehs
,ylitsah ,pu dekcab eH
tsewhtron eht morf senob dlo ekil dehcrap dna dloc
.yresrun lacol eht morf revotfel neeb dah revetahw tsuj erew yeht won tub
,stnemgarf ecnef nettogrof-gnol dna deew dna levarg fo rennam lla htiw delbmut ,sdnas ehT
dog sih yaw eht lla dna ,ysatsce fo etats a ni epol gnitae-elim a deklaw eH
-dna ,ti dah d’eh elihw
.xaler neht ,psag reh was eH
,tuctrohs a gniredisnoc rof thgir mih devreS
,lacirotehr gnieb ylno saw ngis eht fo tsohg eht detcepsus eh tuB
,niaga dias eh ,reciffo ,hguorht gnissap ylno m’I
?ylerus ,elihw a edor dna tekcit a thguob eh fi thgirla eb d’tI
.mraw peek ot gninaem er’uoy fi
?morf detrats d’eh erehw gniredisnoc cinori taht t’nsaw dna
,rof depoh eh dlrow eht mih wohs peels tel
,ksam a saw wenk eh erutcip a dna dezingocer regnol on eh eman a dias taht eno eht
dog sih fo ecneserp eht otni mih thguorb tsrif dah
.tbuod yawa yrrac dluow mutnemom sepoh ni
yawa raf dehcterts
.sih teem ot denrut yeht nehw sthgildaeh ekil dezalb seye ehT .thgil lacaidoz
,yloh saw ,thgin siht ,klaw siht nosaer revetahw rof fi dnA
.gnipeew tnelis htiw tew era yehT
.gnihtaerb sa larutan sa saw ti denrael uoy ecno tub
,sdik ,emoh ta siht yrt t’nod ,ecaf sih morf sehcni ,tsap dehsalf smaeb eltsert leets ehT
.ycrem taerg s’dog sih ni ,kcaP enO
,decaf eh tahw erew yeht os
meht rof deyarp eH .ot deen uoy fi
ytilauxesomoh ro
,siht ezisahpme ot detnaw sitruC dna ”,yltsom tuB“
,esolc tog uoy sa noos sa
.ecnatsid eht ni mih gnizilatnat llits sniatnuom esoht tsap tog eh retfa
,stsif otni pu dellab sdnah reh dah ehs kcab kool deltrats a tohs eh nehW
,seenk sih ot llef
tnenitnoc elohw eht ot tlit elbissop tsethgils eht
.flow tnargav dlo ynwarcs eno naht ees ot ewa fo lluf erom thgis a evah d’yeht ,llew ,ereht SAW esle enoyna fi dnA
!ytinummoc siht fo nerdlihc eht fo ytefas eht tuoba erac ot neppah I“ ,deppans ehs
.noitpircsed dnoyeb derit dna tfos saw eciov reH
deciton t’ndah rehtie ehs taht sknaht evag sraet deifirret hguorht dna
,ksam namuh ruoy dniheb edih nac uoy flow eht tsuj naht erom s’ereht dna
.esimorp a saw sihT
,daor eht ffo deppets eH
,yhw ,smra s’rehtom ni gnimaercs ,tnafni eht nevE
.efil siht ni ton ,erom rof ksa ot demuserp evah ton dluow eH
tuoba klat ot tnemom a evah uoy od“
.keew eht fo syad dna setad ekil sgniht namuh fo kcart tpek llits yromem sih fo strap revetahw gnihcraes ,skcart sih ni deppots eH
?og ot eerf I mA .edisni
,erehwon fo elddim eht ni tuo
drow tsal eht ekat tsuj
,evots eht no gnitrofmoc dna mraw gnihtemos dna
,tcatnoc eye ekam ot ton
namow a tem eh ,sdnalrevir eht fo tsdim eht ni erehwemoS
,em deyarteb evah regnuh fo ssenkaew ym ton tel
.nworht d’ehs tcejbo eht pu dekcip dna tneb eh
.os dias eh fi ,erac t’ndluow ehs detcepsus eh dna
.nialpxe ylthgir t’ndluoc eh owt ro gniht a nees d’eh sa wolla dluow sitruC ,seY
thgin mraw a saw ti tuB
,mih htiw deklaw dog siH
denniht evoba sduolc eht sa
.dereviuq spil reH
.sih ton tub ,hguone tsaf neeb ev'dluoc smrof namuh emoS
os setalp cinotcet eht epahs ot
,gnitfird skcap tfel tahT
.nur ot detnaw eh dna rebbur dezinacluv dna redwopnug dna hcaelb ekil dellems ehs
nevaeh llits saw ti tub ,eson namuh a ot yldneirfnu dellems evah dluow ylbaborp dna
.daeh sih fo kcab eht no
.tfihs ot evah t’ndid eh ,sselnoom saw thgin eht ,oN ?lluf ehs saW
,enohpyap a revo noitasrevnoc A
gnisir si noom tsevrah a roF
,gnisufnoc eb dluoc tI
.dias eh ,kcap lufrednow a tog uoY
.yawa dna revir eht ssorca mih erob niart eht sa hsinav ecneserp eht tlef eH
t’ndid ti ,ti ot laiceps gnihton saw ereht
,meht ta kool ot nwonk evah t’ndluow uoY
.enog saw eh emit tsap saw tI
.ecno ta lla raeh ot tol a saw ti ecneirepxe morf wenk eH
.setteragic eht ot txen dna noitceles yrettol ffo-hctarcs eht evoba
.sgnilbis flow rieht yb dniheb tfel eb t’ndluow yeht
dereviled ma I sdnah esohw otni resucca eht siht ot ssentiw enrob evah ton mih tel
.yromem on saw sihT
.egamirglip siht detrats eh nehw dniheb sgniht namuh tfel d’eH
niaga raf sa tsuj klaw flesmih edam eh
.noitcidsiruj ym fo tuo dedaeh er’uoy tuB“
.swodniw eht hguorht tesnus eht
.kcab pils ti tel neht
.dluoc ehs erofeb yawa deklaw d’eh yrgnA
.rissoN ?won ereh eb oT
,dias ylno eh duol tuo tub—
,eh naht elbirret erom dna retaerg dna reithgim flow a saw dog tub
.ybab eht hsuh ot deganam dah ,triks eht ni ,rehto ehT .deipucco dik eht peek ot gniyrt saw ,snaej eulb eht ni ,nemow eht fo enO
tcetorp nac ew yaw ylno eht s’tI
,t’ndid ehs fi neve ,wenk eh dna
.eciov ruoy ni pu gniwohs
.mrots gnisnaelc a sgnirb ti dna gnisir si noom tsevrah eht roF
.toof no tsae eunitnoc ot krap dedoow eht hguorht kcud ot ydaer dna
yletarebiled ti deppord dna
”!snomed fo stros lla yb dessessop teg elpoeP“ .raed hO
.yks thgin eht tsniaga kcalb repeed ylthgilS
,daor eht ffo delbmuts eh erofeb
ees dluoc eh esuaceB
.foor eht fo skaep eht ni swodniw hgih ,skcirb yssom dna sgol tuc erauqs
.erofeb hcum sa enod d’eH .ti gnissorc tuoba smlauq on dah eH
.taht htiw ecaep ta eb dluoc eH
.revir ippississiM eht saw ereht
msiripmav neve ro tfarchctiw ro
?noom eht ti saw ,tiaW
,elims yhtrowtsurt a delims
.rehtruf yna mih truh t’ndluoc tI
,sdnah sih otni ti devohs ehS
.erif lanif eht etingi dloc tsom snrub ecnaegnev esohW eH teL
,mih dewohs ti egdol eht ot neeb reven dah eh roF
mih deksa redluohs gnipeew-rat s’yawhgih eht yb ngis dedaf ehT
”!noitan siht fo lortnoc ekat ot gniyrT !thgim
”,ni uoy ekat dluoc I“
,delbmuts dna depmuj eH
.tnafni na ,dlihc a
?ti si ,thgin rehto yna ekil gniklaw tsuj reve si thgindim tsap gniklaw tuo er’uoy nehw thgin on dna
kcab dekool eh fi erus saw eh os
hguohT .deroda srehtaferof ruo taht ratla dna htrae fo dog eht fO
.htob ro ecalp siht ot ro
,mih ot defashcuov neeb dah flow eht fo ssenlluf eht erofeb neve dna ,noitats sag a edistuo hcneb a tsuj ,gnidliub a t’nsaw erehT .yllaer ,pots a
,yhtrow erew ohw snamuh ot evig ot ,won ,srieht saw ti sA
.ecneirepxe ydob fo tuo on ,ecnart on ,noisiv on saw tI
,tes eno ylno ees dluow eh
emoceb dah lla esuaceb emoclew eb dluow lla erehw
taeh yawhgih eht ni swodahs-retaw ekil dehsinav taht sboj gnisahc
hctip reh fo tsom hguorht deirruh dah ehs
,yrtnuoc eht fo trap siht htiw railimaf yltcaxe t’nsaw eH
.owt ro ytnewt a ,seitfif ,sderdnuH
.edisni peed deretaw era yehT
”?ereh ssenisub ruoy si tahw riS“
ot kaeps ot tnaw I‘ yas ot derreferp evah d’ehs ekil dednuos taht
,truh ot hguone yvaeh t’nsaw tI
,elbat cincip eht ta meht tfel eH
-fo drow eht daerps ot gniyrt osla m’I ,ma’am uoy knaht on yas ot woh derebmemer dna gnitoof sih dnuof d’eh emit eht yb dnA
.dias eh ,ti tsap teg ll’uoy dna gniklaw peeK
redlo siH .eno meht evag dna
.dewobnu gniw s’rorret yb sevorg elppa ni ti detsat evah I
.flesmih ot dias eh
tnih eht koot eH
,ereh tsuj htuos revir eht tnes
,saw eh sa dlo sa tsomla saw ehS
,yenruoj siht detrats eh nehw ,sgniht fo tol a tcepxe ot flesmih thguat d’eH ”?raeh reve
.revo ti dednah dna
!em dna uoy ekil snaciremA thgirpu tneced nopu yerp ot
?flesmih sa ,ot thguo eh sa
ydob ruoy fo gnileef eht ekil
nworb namuh morf ,eye sih tsuj
fo serutcip gnikat eb ot demees yeht ylikcul tub
?detserra gnieb eh saw tub ,niaga neppah t’ndluow ti depoh eh
,wenk eh ,hcruhc a raen erehwyna neeb t’ndah eH
?detserra gnieb I ma ,reciffo ,rof tahW
?dnuof eb dluoc ti retne ot yaw eht ylno fi
,lirep fo ruoh siht ni em dnefed tseW tsomrettU eht ni droL ho—
.ralloc eht ot dennip galf naciremA lemane ynit a htiw ’MOM EGAREVA
.flowerew gnilliw a tem txen sitruC revenehw
.t’nsaw ti ,taht ekil tlef siht sa hcum sA
,nees dah triks eht ni rehtom eht erus saw
.erised fo sworra dna dlog gninrub fo wob ym gnirb oS  .desoppus eh
.deralf slirtson reH
,thgilerif eht nees
”?ytinretE dnepS uoY lliW erehW“
,egdirb eht erofeb dewols dah ti dna
,tog uoy sworros dna sfeirg revetahw htiw laed tsuJ
mih tih gnihtemoS
,llew ,ees dluoc eh meht neewteb ni tub
,mrofinu nworb psirc a ni spil gnivorppasid dna nub ednolb thgit
,sehtolc sih ffo deppirts eH
evreserp dna eziromem ot
.erab erew sregnif s’nam eht
,dias eh ,reciffo ,gnihtoN
”,DI ruoy ees ot deen I“
neht dna ,kcap eno eb d’ereht dna ,meht nioj dna
,retlehs gnikat eb tseb d’uoy oS nrolrof eht rof ,taf eht rof gnignahc-a era yeht ,semit eht dnA
.derettups nam eht ”,tpecca t’nac I“
,desoppus eh ,deifirret neeb evah dluow yeht daor eht nwod niaga ffo tes dna sdoow eht fo tuo pu kcab emac tahw gnihctaw neeb dah dog sih tub enoyna fI
?enoemos ot klat ot ecnahc a dah eh emit txen yrots siht esu eh dluohS
dias dna roloc elgnis a ni detnirp saw tnorf ehT
s’flah dna dnoces a tog ehs
yllacitnarf gniyarp saw eh dnim sih ni dna
.ehcadaeh a mih evig ot nugeb dah eson sih gnidnilb enilosag fo llems ehT ”!seitinummoc ruo
:eb dluow stekcit eht erehw wonk ot
,yhW ?daor eht no neeb sitruC dah gnol woH
.sthgil der dna eulb fo tsrub lufniap eht fo tuo mih drawot deklats
,emoclew saw eh mih llet
,etatsretni eht fo raor eht revo ton ,ereh morf raeh t’ndluoc eH
.tnaem ti tahw nwonk t’ndah ro
,nedrub rehtona dniheb tfel d’eh ekiL
,gniveirg morf tser dnif dna ,kcap eht htiw nur luos sih yam—
.htron deklaw eh oS
.oot did eh esruoc fo oS
.DI eht ta dekool ehS
.tey mih tsurt ot nosaer yna evah t’ndid yeht
.kaeps ton did doG .erus saw eh
.rednuht tnatsid sa tfos si tI
.meht wonk ot kool ot deen t’ndid eH
,meht hguorht no sserp tsuj
:dednamed taht eciov detrotsid-enohpagem a saw ereht dna
,kcurts daeh-hctam eht nees evah seye eniM
.erom peels eht dedeen uoy ekil em ot dekool tub
ti dellac eH .kcirt eht htiw pu emoc dah—
.ylimaf flowerew a otni nar eh ytiC amohalkO fo tsew syaw emos pots tser a nI
,deddap dna dewalc
,eb dluoc htrae elbeef siht no gnihtyna sa ti ot raen sa ,llew—
noinim a era uoY !uoy hsinomda I“
droffa nac I n’erom si dnal desimorp taht litnu tsal ot
.gnihton dias eH .sthgil gnihsalf htiw mih gnidnilb eno eht saw noitcerid yna ni rac ylno ehT
,ti fo gnileef eht sdrow otni tup ot drah oot
.mih rof tnaem tsuj neeb dah siht ebyaM
?enoyna dedneffo t’nevah I epoh I ,reciffo gniklaw ylno m’I
noitaniccav fo snomed“
.elbat cincip eht dehcaorppa dna dnim sih pu edam eH
.sbrubus eht ro ,seitic eht ot esolc oot erew esoht
.egdirb yawliar eht
.ecalp hguone tnasaelp
,adaveN dellac nwot a tsap ruoh na flah tuoba ,tsae gnidaeh saw eH
.tnaem sitruC tahw wonk did eH
.mih saw ti htob ot yaw eht wonk ot devresed enoyna fi rof
cinatas fo secrof ehT“
.ebirt ym lla fo sluos eht ni detnalp era htarw fo separg ehT  .snialp eht
?ees uoy ,ecnedivorP
,denetsil rekcurt eht dnA
.erudne lliw I ,teg reven ll’I sgniht eht rof nodnaba tsum I evol roF
.eman sih rof deksa reven dah sitruC taht
,lla retfa ,tcatnoc eye edam eH
,floW eht ot gnidroccA lepsoG eht morf gnidaeR A
.yawa ,ocixeM weN fo tser eht dna ,yad eht tpels eH
,peelsa llaf uoy erofeb tsuj
,etib eht dna kcap eht tuoba mih dlot I tahw detroper evah ton mih tel ,krap eht ni ot deklat I allef gnuoy eht
taht uoy llet reve enoyna diD
.shtom fo yxalag yredwop nwo sti dah thgilteerts negolah thgirb-godnus yreve dna
.dluoc eh fi ,meht pleh ot ebyaM .dnah ta saw
.ti thguac evah t’ndluoc eh detfihs neeb ydaerla t’ndah eh fi llits tub
,edisni pets ot denrut eh sa namow a dias ”,em esucxE“
,epoh tuohtiw dnA
.pots a ot emoc dog tlef eh
,iruossiM fo edis rehto eht ot tog eh nehW
.sitruC uoy teem ot ecin s’ti ,dias eh ,lleW
.gninetsil t’nsaw ehs tub ,dluoc eh sa yletilop sa nodrap reh deggeb eH
,tuo senohp rieht dah yeht ,gnirats erew noitats sag eht ni elpoeP
.denediw seye reH .yad dooG
,ecnedivorp fo tnemurtsni eht saw flowerew eht woh tuoba meht dlot eH
,niereht ecalp a fo reffo ym ta esneffo on nekat evah mih tel
.sitruC ot gnidrocca saxeT nrehtron ni ,pots a ta pu dellup kcurt ehT
.esrow gnitteg saw ehcadaeh taht ,hO
.ti fo thguoht nus eht tahw dnim uoy reven
,gnissarah neeb d’ehs retfird sselemoh eht saw sa desserd
.wal eht fo luofa nar eh iruossiM nI
,floWcaM boR yb ,floW eht ot gnidroccA lepsoG eht morf gnidaeR A yojne esaelP
,dlrow desimorp eht
seirots eht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,rac xob eht fo edis eht no reddal a thguac
.thgindim retfa emit emos tsae denrut htron dewollof eh daor ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy syawla sA
.ynomrah a dna mhtyhr a otni denrut—
,oga snoe ,tif nees dah ecnedivorp fI
,gnilliw dog ,worromoT
ylimaf a htiw eno ton yllaicepse ,flowerew a rof efas toN
.rac dauqs eht ot
.etteragic a gniffuns fi sa levarg edisdaor eht otni elostoob eno detsiwt
tniaf eht tsniaga elbisiv elzzum
,won thgirla saw eH
.retaw eht dessorc ti sa no gnuh
eh os dnoces a ti dleH .dlog flow ot
.kcab s’rekrowesac .M.P.E fo .B a dniheb thgir ti enod ecno daH .kniw flow eht
.mih demialc peels erofeb
dna dnim gnicar sih neewteb
,thgir lla saw tahT
,egaruoc rieht pu peek ot meht llet ot meht ot mih dediug dah ,ylraelc ,ecnedivorP
dehcaer eh erofeb ,setunim ylno neeb evah thgim ti ,sruoh neeb evah thgim tI
,doohdlihc fo renroc nettogrof a morf ,yromem mid a ekil saw tI
.siht etapicitna ot thguoht t’ndah eh tub
,ylevitroppus ton dna
.seert eht naht regraL .epahs a tsuj
.ti tnaem dah ti yhw
dias taht trihstaews yffulf a erow ehS
.llew sksam rieht erow lla yeht
,emahs a saw taht saw dias eh lla tub—
.meht hguorht teg lliw uoy tub hguorht og ot tog uoy semit eht riaf t’nsi ti dnA
.rehgih esir dniw dliw siht dna dlofnu sduolc dedworc eht tel oS
.eltsihw eht draeh eh neht dnA
tnatropmi os s’ti yhw s’taht dna-
,yalp riaf ylno si tuobanrut eugra dluow ohw
.no sserp ot teef sih ot flesmih dellup eh ,htgnel tA .flesmih ot netsil ot seirt wef a koot tI ?thgiR ?thgir
.tcelgen gnol hguorht elats dna ruos enog
.niaga ecno yawhgih eht dna thgin eht ot
,dlrow namuh eht fo eow eht odnu ot ereh
,eromyna yrgna t’nsaw nam ehT
.sitruC saw eman s’rekcurt ehT
.tuoba yrrow ot nerdlihc dna
,eludehcs no snur gnikam tuoba erac I
.tuo emac srats eht dna
.dlo oot tib elttil a tsuj dna llams oot tib elttil a tsuj rac A
.flesmih ot dias eh
eht rof tsuj ,flesmih eb ot tsuj flesmih eb ot nettog d’eh ecnis emit gnol gnol a neeb ti t’ndaH
ngier eerf evah lliw
”,DI ruoy ees ot deen I“
,ekam ot detnaw uoy hctip tolip-yks atros emos dah uoy esoppus I
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.renialp eb ot ti ksa t’ndluoC
sdnuos eno tsal taht wonk I woN“ ...oooon
morf ti peek ot nac uoy regna eht lla gniwollaws er’uoy erehw dnik eht
eseht fo hguone nees d’eh
,eye sih detfihs eH
,gniklaw tsuj t’nsaw ti ,oN
.drow ym evah uoy taht nO
.sllib fo lufdnah a mih dednah dna tekcop ytsud sih ni gud eH .ereH
.syaw trap ew erehw s’sihT“
,mih ta gnihgual saw sitruC kniht ot
”W“ elbuod elttil eht
.duol yrev eb noos lliw tI
.desnaelC .rethgil tlef eh
wodniw edis regnessap reh hguorht kool doog
.retaL .srewsna sih htiw od ot sgniht tnatropmi erom dah eH
.sevlowerew ni eveileb t’ndid ohw
os nerdlihc namuh sih ot etib tsrif eht fo tfig eht nevig dah dog-flow eht woh denialpxe eH .gnimoc saw
,htab mraw a otni gnippils ekil ,ylisae ,ylhtoomS
.thgin rehto yna ekil tsuJ
.mrof ekat sdaehrednuht eht sa enozo eht tlems sah eson yM
.kcab ti evig t’ndiD
.dias ehs ”?uoy pleh I naC“
,renroc eht denrut ehs sa ,tuo llup did ehs nehw oS
stnirptoof nwo sih ni yltcefrep dednal yeht dna
,mih dniheb yltneg rood eht desolc
.tleb sih htiw meht deit
.gniklaw tsuj saw ti tsrif tA
.luos sih fo stoor eht ot yraew saw eh dna—
.rehtona ro ynapmoc eno rof ,won sraey evif tuoba daor eht no neeb dah sitruC
.VUS etihw gib reh pu gnillif morf yawa deppets tsuj dah dna
.sneris draeh eh nehW
,desoppus eh ,kcap a ni gnitnuh ot desU
luos sih ni ti dah evah eh dluoc
.ti fo kcis naht erom era dna ecnelis eht draeh evah srae eniM
,niaga ksam namuh sih dniheb neddih ydaerla saw eh tohsrae fo tuo erew serit gnilaeuqs eht emit eht yB
.dnim on me yap t’nod I“
,mih ot edutitarg fo ,sitruC fo rettam eht dettimmoc eH
esolc t’nsaw ti ro
.ti esu ot dediced ehs fi neppah dluow tahw
,tsom naht yletilop erom
.ksam namuh sih ffo koot eh
.nworb krad erew sworbeye reh tub etihw yrevlis dehcaelb saw riah reH
.revir eht yb daor a tsuj t’nsaw ti dna
.tsugsid lufworros ni
.ti eveileb t’ndid eh wenk dnA .gnihtyna NAEM
etiB eht tpecca dluow ,eno yb eno ,snamuh eht lla yademoS .deksa ohw
,kcap taerg eht fo yad eht
hguorht niaga htron deklaw eh sa
.dog sih fo tnecs eht niaga dellems ,nihtiw ssenkrad gnimoclew eht nees reveN
,retnuoc eht dniheb ,edisni
.hsiloof kool meht edam ev'uoy fi
,ssensselhtaerb gningief ,no tnew ehs
,nemow owt ,nam A .meht dehctaw eH
ekomsdoow dna esnecni saw htaenrednu tub
?yloh gnihtemos fo trap erew uoy
.erit yeht tsal ta erofeb
,no desserp eh os ,sworbeye delzzup emos werd tahT
,ffurcs ,srae fo eniltuo erem ehT
ssenredliw sseldne s’kcap eht ni eerf nur luos sih yam—rehtorb
”.ti rof gnitsub m’I ssa esohw wonk I gnissim seog mug gniwehc fo kcits a sa hcum os emit txen eht ro
.tirw secaf dnasuoht a nopu riapsed daer evah seye eniM
,tsol dna ,deirrow dna ,derit dellems yehT
,tsugsid taerg htiw ,oS
.mih ta dereens ehs
.ti miws dluoc namuh a ebyaM
,tey eryp eno tsael ta no eldnik tsum I taht semalf roF
.ti gnidloh neeb ydaerla evah tsum ehS ’?UOY SNWO OHW‘
,noitangiser taerg htiW
.deklaw eh sa flesmih ot demmuh eH
.pu denethgiarts yeht sa resolc dlihc evitcepser rieht llup htob meht dehctaW
”?aera siht ni ssenisub ruoy si tahW“
ti ni eb ot evresed eh t’ndid
kcap taerg a taht dna
,til sah ti taht semalf roF
.tuo tsurht nihc reh
.ffuts eht rof esu erom yna dah EH ekil t’nsaW
ydob ruoy ylluf ton gnieb
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dnA
degnahc dnim sih ni reyarp ehT
,gniklaw peek uoy oS
.htron ,llew ,eb dluow siuoL .tS wenk eh tub
enot a ni ,dias ehS ”!rail s’nataS er'uoy sevorp tsuj ti gniyneD !egadnob ni uoy sah nataS
”,adaveN ni kcab loohcs a yb gnissap dethgis erew uoY“
,gnihtyreve fo ytilanimil eht fo ,ti fo elgnit eht leef dluoc eH