.thgit oot saw taorht ym tub
”.ppa thgilhsalf ruoy pu llup si pleh ot od dluoc uoy tsael ehT
.ediw tuo swap sih gnidloh ,dias fieL
,pot eht ta tesnus eht ta tuo dekool elpoep esuaceb ”htaP tesnuS“ dellac saw siht thguoht I“
kooL .boj thgir eht s’ti
”?thgir ,tuo siht erugif ot emit tog ev’eW
”.gnikcinap eht lla neewteb ni taht ezeeuqs ot yrt ll’I“ .dekrims I
.raey namhserf ym detrats I erofeb msilanruoJ dekcip I ecnis reve taht em debbud dah fieL
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.em ot resolc ni denael dna smra ym debbarg eH
erot trihs ym fo tnorf ehT
.enog saw eciov ym nevE
”!og tel woN .ysae kool ti ekam uoY“
”.enilno scip esoht was I“
,hguoht ylsuoireS
.leehw gnireets a ekil mih fo tnorf ni ria eht gnipsarg
.daeh sih koohs eh tub ,tuo dehcaer I
”?thgir ,noitisop level-yrtne na rof ecneirepxe eht evah tsael ta dluohs I
,yaw gnorw eht siht ekat t’noD“
.ecnuob lufecarg a fo erom dah I .did fieL ,lleW
krad saw ti esuaceb ttub daeh elttil a mih evag I
?erutnevda na rof ruoh rehtona s’tahW .no
.buc a llits m’I ,stnerap ym ot derapmoc tub ,dlo repus leef em sekam tahT
”.lliw I ,pam eht kcehc t’now uoy fI“
”?ekil kool taht s’tahW“
trid eht otni sregnif ym gud I
.deksa I ”?taht dexif evah dluow kcor a gnihcuot dnA“
.seeyolpme rieht evig serots yrecorg eht sruoh dna segaw riafnu eht tuoba etirw ot tnaw I
”?yadirF no uoy rof og weivretni taht d’woh ,yaw eht yB
”.gnihtemos ro ekal eht dnuora pal a ekat ot gniog tsuj erew ew thguoht I“
”.ti hcuot annog er’ew dnA“
.nus gniknis eht ta despmilg I
.denettalf srae s’fieL
”?tey dial teg uoY
”?yako ,klaw tsuj s’teL“
”.TI OD .em dna uoY
”.boj maerd taht teg ll’uoy ,kcor eht hcuot uoy ecno ebyam ,yeH
.snwog noitaudarg rieht rednu stius ssenisub gniraew ydaerla saw ssalc gnitaudarg sih fo flah ekil saw ti ,yllautcA
”snoilliM gnomA kcoR A“
.dias fieL ”,celA ,ecalp dab a ni er’uoY“
”.kcab daeh tsuj s’teL .revetahW“
!llits tub ,yadrutaS rehto yreve ,ekil ,ylno ,yakO !syadrutaS .edud
.celA ,pot eht ot og ot evah eW“
,gnilims t’nsaw eH .dias fieL
emoC“ ”.srewop cigam evah t’nod skcoR“
.ffilc ykcor a fo esab eht ta seert fo gnirehtag eht ot detniop eh sa
”.taht ekil eb t’nod ,celA“
,ylper on gnitteg dna remmus lla semuser tuo gnidnes retfA
# ”?pu sdael eseht fo eno hcihW“
,htuom ym denepo dna
.yawa ti dettaws I tub ,em no wap sih tup eH
.yks eht tuo kcolb ot hguone raf tuo hcaer t’ndid seert eht ,dnal fo tips siht nO
”,efil hguorht teg ot wonk ot deen uoy gnihtemos s’erehT“ ”.etepmoc t’nac I
”,kcor siht s’ereht ,laer rof tub ,oN“
,detnap eH ”.erus ytterP“
”.gnikil ruoy rof hguone y-odneunni tsuj sdnuos ’ecnarusni
”?gnihtemos ro noisiv thgin evah uoy t’noD“
.daeh sih koohs eilloc ehT
”.htaerb ym hctac ot
”?taht ekil noitseuq a ekat ot esoppus I ma yaw fo dnik lleh eht tahW“
.edis sih otno gnillor ,dias fieL
”.hceeps lanoitavitom ruoy si sihT .em ta kool t’noD“
.htap eht morf gnignah
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.hcraes ruo gnirud nees d’I tahw naht erom saw ti ,llitS
”?’ycilop ecnarusni na yub s’tel ,yeH‘ ,gnikniht yb dnekeew eht strats ohW
.pu swap ym gnittup ,deffocs I ”,em esucxe lleW“
taes sih tsniaga depmuht liat siH
”?detrats remmus eht ecnis sboj eerht ,ekil ,dereffo neeb uoy t’nevaH“ .delbmurg I
.gnihtemos eht ot revo decar ew dna ,redluohs ym debbaj fieL
.eno fo kcal ro erutuf ym fo deracs saw ohw toidi na saw I esuaceb dneirf tseb ym dellik I .hturt eht tsuj
.reffo boj a otni denrut hcihw ,weivretni dnoces a otni denrut hcihw ,weivretni na otni denrut hcihw ,llac enohp a tog I nehT
.redluohs sih revo dekool I
”,gnikcinap t’nsaw I esuaceb tsrif ta yppah saw I“
”?em rof dehcysp elttil a teg tsael ta uoy naC“
.enim ot esolc ecaf sih devohs fieL
.ti fo tuo gnikcits gniht a htiw gnihtemos ylniatrec saw erehT .detniuqs I
laiceps erom wohemos s’ti esuaceb kcor a hcuot nac uoy os etib gub rehtona teg ot dnuora gnikcits ton m’I tub ,tsrif ta nuf saw siht ,kooL“
”.noitanibmoc gninniw eht ekil mees seod tahT“
.meht ssorca pets ot dah ew os
?ti tuoba tnatropmi os s’tahW
,dias fieL ”!yaw oN“
.mra ym gnibbarg ,dias fieL ”!no dloH“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.pot eht ot gniog er’ew dnA“
”,neppah ot gniog s’tahw s’ereh ,oN“
”!krap eht fo pot eht raen erehwyna t’nsi sihT“
.emuser ym meht gnivig rebmemer t’nod I tub ,riaf boj a ta erew yeht kniht I“
.gniretlaf elims sih
”.eivom txen sih ni trap a em teg ll’eh dna liat s’god emos no nalp ecnarusni eht od ll’I ebyam ,swonk ohW
.dneirf tseb ym redrum tsomla tsuj t’ndid I dna gnillihc erew ew ekil kool d’ti ,su dnuof regnar krap a fI
.shtap tnereffid eht lla drawot gnitniop sworra htiw dengis eht ta pu dekool I .dias I
”.eno ekil leef I tub ,sknahT“ .detrons I
.egelloc hguorht lla spihsnretni enod ev’I tub ,tops a em dereffo llits yehT“
”?ereht tsomla er’ew erus er’uoY“
.revetahw ro uoy ot meht erapmoc t’nod
”?sgnilbis ruoy ot derapmoC“
,dias fieL ”,elbatrofmocnu repus yllautca si kcor sihT“
.gninepo erots yrecorg wen a tuoba selcitra gnitirw yug eht eb ot tnaw t’nod I
”.slliks noitagivan ym ni htiaf emos evah ,no emoC“
retsim ,erutnevda fo esnes ruoy s’erehw ,no
.enohp ym derewol I
”.gniog er’ew erehw ees ylerab nac ew dna ,krad s’ti
”.nwod kcab og ot gnol taht dna ereht teg ot spot ruoh flah a eb ll’tI
”?ybbat retroper evitagitsevni
”.’slrig hcnerF ruoy fo eno ekil em tniap‘ em evig won ,yakO“
”?dekan em htiw tub ,niaga cip eht ekat uoy nac tub
”.ti ta emosewa eb dna uoy od tsuJ
.tsehc ym no swap ym detser I
.htap eht fo egde eht revo delbmut tsomla dna drawrof deppets I .dellac I ”?fieL-
.mih rof ekops liat sih fo gnihsiws eht tub
.no deyalp surohc tekcirc a dna
,dias fieL ,sdnoces wef a retfA
”,enutrof doog sgnirb tI“
,sgnilbis ruoy yllaicepse ,elpoep rehto ot semoc ti nehW“ .dias fieL
,lwocs em ees t’ndluow fieL os mih dniheb llef I
”!dab yM .ekal eht ta ton
,dias fieL ”,pu tuhS“
.no ppa thgilhsalf eht denrut dna enohp ym pu dleh I ,ereht tog ew nehW
.dluoc I sa raf sa ti kcuhc ot gniog saw I ,no deppets I elbbep txen ehT .dehca shgiht yM
”.rehtegot cinap nac ew
.tuctrohs a llems dluoc eh ekil ria eht gniffins ,sgnidnuorrus eht dennacs eH
rac lortap gnitiawa na ot del gnieb sffucdnah ni flesym ees dluoc I
”.gnihtyna ro uoy hcnup ot gniog t’nsaw I“
”,em dellik evah dluoc uoY“ .dias I ”,dab yM“
.kcab yaw ym gnikam ydaerla
.tniop emos ta pu pop lliw gnihtemoS .orb yrros ,tihS“
.dias fieL ”,htaP tesnuS ehT“
’?tahw won‘ ,ekil ,saw I
.thginot rethgirb demees htap ym tub
,tnuoc nac I naht semit erom boj msilanruoj taht ot deilppa ev’I“
,dneirf tseb ym s’fieL
.dias fieL ”,tac a er’uoy tuB“
,dias fieL ”,rac ynapmoc teews a mih evag ti ,saw ti revetahW“
.hguone riaF“ .deggurhs I
.oot gnihgual flesym dnuof I dna dehgual fieL
.ti tuc syawla t’nseod htiaf dnilB“ .dias I
.eugnot sih fo pit eht ffo gnippird avilas fo tib a
.ecap ym hctam ot dewols eh tub
,gnivil a rof od I tahw em sksa enoemos nehw dezilaer I erom eht
.kraP ekaL kaO fo tol gnikrap eht otni dellup eh sa dias fieL
.kcab ym otno gnillor ,dias I
”!ereh skcor rehto noillim eht naht
.tekcop sih otni enohp sih gnivohs
.ereh morf raf taht ton s’kcor ehT“
”,boj ecnarusni siht tog I woh wonk neve t’nod I“
.swalc ym dnetxe ot ton redrah gnitteg saw tI
.regnif ym htiw noom tnecserc eht decart I
.won sraey owt rof eno dah s’ehS“
”,ereh saw ti erows I“
”.noos boj a gnitrats er’uoy dna ,egelloc doog a otni teg ot deganam llits ,loohcs hgih hguorht yaw ruoy detsaoc uoy ,dedaol s’ylimaf ruoY“ .dias I
?retteb thgin siht ekam d’tahw wonk uoY
”,gnikcinap llits m’I ,lleH“
.edis sih yb tlenk dna nwod deppoh I
liat‘ ,sulP .ti od dluoc uoY
.dias fieL ”,yrettab ym deniard reilrae pam eht gnikcehC“
.eralg s’nus eht morf seye ym dedleihs I
.ti dehcuot htob ev’ew litnu gnivael ton m’I
”,kcor a ton er’uoY“ ”.kcor a ekil m’I
,noitciF degnaF hguorht ygolohtna citore yrruf a
”,emosewa si krap siht ,eduD“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,tniop a ekam ot fi sA
”.truh evah t’ndluow ti ,lleW“
.dne no gnidnats ruf eht
,kcor eht fo trap reinnus eht otni liat sih detfihs eh sA ”!erutcip ym ekaT“
,krad eht ot gnitsujda seye ym ro noitullop thgil fo kcal eht saw ti ebyaM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,daer yllanogaid drawnwod gnitniop ngis ralugnatcer A
”,tniop eht ton s’tahT“
,boj a uoy gnireffo pu swohs enoemos fI“
,syadrutaS krow ot evah I dnA“
”?rehtorb ruoy dnA“
.boj ecnarusni taht trats I erofeb modeerf fo keew a tog ev’I“
.nwod kcab uoy yrrac dna pu uoy kcip ot gniog m’I !raews I
.htaerb god y-lleB ocaT fo lluf repsihw a ni em ot ekops eH
”.thgil enohp llec ym tog llits ev’I“
,sessalc thgir eht lla koot I
.yaw eht fo tuo hcnarb eert gnignah a devohs eH ”?keew elohw eht tub
”.seod tahw wonk t’nod I ,laem eerf a em nrae t’nseod taht fI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
dnal fo tuj yhtrae na no kcab sih no yal fieL
.reklat htooms a er’uoy dna yldneirf er’uoY“ .deggurhs I
.dnuora gnikool ,dias fieL
”.selcsum yna evah t’nod I esuaceb s’taht tub ,uoy pord thgim I
.daeh sih dniheb swap sih gnicalp ,dias fieL ”,eduD“
.timreh gnidleiw-wasniahc emos dnif dna sdoow eht ni repeed og ton s’teL
.mih ecaf ot revo dellor I .dedda fieL
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
tleb denesool-flah sih morf yawa wap sih koot yllufknaht fieL
.kcab dereggats fieL dna
.amolpid sih htiw egats eht ffo deklaw eh sa boj eht dednah neeb dah rehtorb ym fi saw tI
.kcor diputs a tsuj s’tI“
.dedeeccus ev’ew ,kcor taht dehcuot ev’ew ecnO
.kcor rehtona fo pit eht ta gel eno no doots eh
”.ssenisub gib emos rof gnitnuocca gniod s’eh tuB“ .dias I ”,adniK“
”.nwod kcab daeh nac ew nehT
”.selim 5.1 :retneC rotisiV“
”,dneirfyob a sah ehS“
”.keew tsal ecitcarp rieht dehctaw maet cipmylO eht rof tuocs emos yltnerappA“ .deddon I
.yks thgin eht delkcerf srats fo gnirettaps A
.hcum oot gnitnap morf fieL peek ot noitcetorp hguone dedivorp edahs eht ,liart eht fo trap ysdoow eht deretne ew ecnO
”.taht thguob eH .rac ynapmoc a ton s’tI“
,looc si neht dna won yreve dnoB semaJ ekil yssalc gniog ,gnorw em teg t’noD“
.em eciton t’nod yeht ekil s’ti tub
”?gnirob llits eh sI“ .deksa fieL
.neercs eht no sehctarcs wen yna t’nerew erehT
.enohp sih tuo dellup eh sa dias fieL
,dnaH a flesruoY eviG detide ohw ,bmobknukS yb
”,gniog m’I erehw wonk ot gnitnaw rof em esucxe lleW“
.ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,gniog peek ew fI
,sgel ym dnuora resolc liat ym delruc I
”.tuo dekaerf saw I“ .yllud dias fieL
”.yawa raf smees llits gniht rehtegot-tihs-ym-gnitteg elohw ehT“
”.pets taht em evig dna em eucser dluoc enoemos os enoyreve ta emuser ym werht I
”?enif eb ot gniog s’gnihtyreve taht boj a dna yenom tog ev’uoy ecno kniht uoy ,tahW“
,htap eht fo egde eht revo deppils I
,fieL“ .deppots I sa dias I
.taert a rof gnitiaw saw fieL ekil saw tI .deggaw liat siH
’?rehtob yhw‘ lla eb ll’uoy dna hguone detcejer teg uoY“
.eson ym fo egdirb eht dehcnip I
.ti otni tup I htgnerts hcum woh em desirprus ti tub ,hsup a eb ot desoppus saw tI
.trihs ym fo tnorf eht gnibbarg ,dekrab fieL
.pu fieL dellup dna tuo wap ym kcuts I ”.azziP
.og tel dna ,swap ym yb gnignah
.elzzum sih gnilknirw ,dias fieL
,dias I ”,krad ta sesolc krap eht tuB“
,tenalPruF hguorht WALC dna ,GNAF
.ti koot I dna pets txen ym em evag enoemos taht saw wenk I llA
L“ .ereht t’nsaw eh nehT
.dias I ”,seert eht fo yna kram ot ton yrT“
.ruoh na rof gniklaw neeb ev’eW“
”?ecnarusni lles dluow ohw yug fo dnik eht ekil kool I od
,revetahw ro lacigam t’nsi kcor siht fi neve ,lleW
”,ylsuoires ,yakO“ ”.dab yM“
.erehwyna evird ro niatnuom taht pu ecar ot detpmet saw I
,dedivorp noom eht thgil fo stib tsal eht tuo dekcolb seert gnignahrevo ehT # ”.eniF“
”,seert owt esoht neewteB“ ”?tahW“
.strohs dna tleb sih neewteb regnif a deppils fieL
.enohp ym tuo dellup I
.kniht neve t’ndid I
”.gnivael m’I ,em htiw er’uoy ton ro rehtehw dna ,rac ym ni gnitteg m’I
.tuo gnikop morf swalc ym peek ot thguof I
.ti did I yhw em gniksa ,em gnimraws sretroper eht dna
… setunim wef a … em evig tsuJ“
.gnikiH“ ,gniyas dneirf tseb ym morf txet a ot pu ekow I  bmobknukS yb
”.gnissim s’ehs tahw
on dah I dezilaer I dna retsemes tsal ym otni gniog saw I“ .dias fieL
.rettib sdnuos ydobemoS“ .pu doots dna
”,tius a raew ot evah I tub ,haeY“
dnah ym morf deppils ti ,tekcop ym fo tuo enohp eht dellup I sA
.mih fo stohs kciuq fo elpuoc a deppans dna enohp ym tuo koot I
.rae sih dehctarcs fieL ”.boj thgir ehT“
.tekcop ym otni enohp ym deppils I sa mih dlot I
.ti teg setelhta dna srats pop fo stoL“
.em htaeneb kcalb eht otni gnirats
”.kcor siht dnif nac eW
,neht litnu tuB“ .fieL dias ”,haeY“
.dias I ”,pihsnretni na yllautca saw noitisop eht gniyas liame na ot pu ekow I“
.mih ot txen nwod yal I os ,enoemos revo gnidnats drawkwa s’tI
.mih ot kcab denrut dna smra ym dedlof I
”!pot eht ot teg ot evah eW“
.derewsna stekcirc ylnO ”!fieL“
”?ecnarusni lles ot gnitnaw pu sworg buc tahW
.ecnarusni lles I meht llet ot evah d’I
”.krad s’ti ,tihS“ .dehgis eH
”?reccos egelloc gniyalp llits ehS“
”.ssa ruoy no setib gub teg ll’uoy ,ffo stnap ruoy ekat uoy fi ,oslA
.ti fo tuo lleh eht etah I ro gnillac ym dnif I litnu siht od tsuj ll’I“
,nwod kcab gniog m’I“
.tnemyolpmenu ym morf em tcartsid ,tsael yrev eht ta
.stekcop ym otni devohs swap ym
.htaerb god sih ta eson ym delknirw I
”?uoy t’nera ,efil rof em revo taht dloh ot gniog er’uoY“
”.uoy t’nsaw ti ,oN“ .dehgis I
.ppa thgilhsalf eht pu llup ot enohp ym debbarg I
.reffo eht tog I neht tub ,ecnarusni ni krow ot gnikool t’nsaw I
,retnec rotisiv eht ot htap ykcor eht nwod deklaw ew sA
”,tuo dekrow ti ,lleW“
.eciov sih ni hgual a fo tnih a ,dias fieL ”!tihs hO“
.etartenep t’ndluoc thgis ym ssenkrad a yb dewollaws saw dna
.thginot em dellik tsomla uoY“
.noonretfa na rof tac roodtuo na eb dluoc I derugif I
”.kcoR revO tnemugrA ytteP ni dneirF slliK tnediseR lacoL“
.setunim evif naht ssel ,oN .setunim evif ni ti dnif ew teb I“ .dias fieL
,hcuorc a otni deppils I
,ekal eht gnikoolrevo skcor fo puorg a dnuof fieL
”.deliaf t’nevah ew
.esolc yldesselb dna duol saw eciov siH
.rac eht fo tuo debmilc ew sa dias fieL
.egelloc retfa saw tahw eulc
.ppa thgilhsalf ym dekcilc I
”.gnineppah reveN“ .eson ym delknirw I
”.krap siht revo lla skcor era
,ro daeh ym raelc dluow ria hserf emos ebyaM
,etad trats ym ot tog I resolc eht neht tuB“ .dedda fieL
,dnuorg eht fo tuo dettuj skcoR ”!revetahW“ ”.eciwT“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,laer yllatot s’tI“
.denihw fieL ”!emit eno saw tahT“
.dias fieL ”,tib elttil A“
”?enutrof doog deen uoy od lleh eht yhW“ .delworg fieL
.ekal lavo na ot yaw sti devruc revir A
”snoilliM gnomA kcoR A“   :yojne esaelP
.seitnewt ylrae ruo ni er’ew ,naem I
”!elpmis taht ton s’tI“
?egelloc ni tnemeriuqer fo tros emos dessim I daH
,yrots lanoitasnes a meht evig t’ndluow I
”,cip edun citsitra y-sroodtuo na htiw etad a erocs uoy pleh ot evol d’I .fieL ,sey‘ sa ti ekat uoY“
”,ybraen eb ot sah tI“
erehT“ ”—ereht pu kcor siht s’erehT
”.em fo tuo dekconk … dniw eht tsuJ“
”.eduD“ ”—s’teL“ .dessih I
reh wohS .siht ni retsis ruoy gaT“ ,dias eh
.tuo gnidils swalc ym ,dias I
,RAOR fo snoitide suoirav ni dehsilbup seirots sah dna
.evila erew ew dna
.dnuora gninrut ,dias I ”,gnivael m’I“
,dias I ”,tuo derugif lla ti tog ev’uoy ekil skooL“
.riahc nwal a ekil eno tsniaga kcab yal eh dna
.eb ot naipmylO na dna tnatnuocca retsam A“
.retnec rotisiv eht ot kcab dna ekal eht dnuora elcric thgit a gnikam litnu ylesool decra htaP tesnuS ehT
.gniraebrevo elttil a saw msaisuhtne eninac sih tub
.daeh sih koohs fieL
.nwod dray a tuoba hcuorc a otni llef I
”?retsis ruoy ot ti dnes ot tnaw t’nod uoy erus uoY“ .dias fieL
”.enutrof doog steg ti sehcuot reveohw taht syas dnegeL .kcor eguH“
.gnivaeh tsehc sih
”?boj ecnarusni eht tuoba stnerap ruoy htiw klat uoy diD
.kciht dna hgih eciov ym ,dias I ”?fieL“ ”!elohssA“
”?pu sgniht deeps ew fi dniM“
.daer dluow repap s’worromot ni enildaeh eht tahw dna siht ekil yrots a gnirevoc ekil eb d’ti tahw derednow I
.em ot txen enots eht ssorca gnihcni rallipretac yggahs a ta decnalg I
,ti naem t’ndid I !yrros os m’I“
emoC“ .pirg sih denesool eH
”,gnihcraes boj no desucof m’I“
,bmobknukS yb ”snoilliM gnomA kcoR A“ saw sihT
”.gniyub er’uoy fi ,doog sdnuoS“
.rae sih gnihctarcs ,dias fieL
.dnuorg eht morf enohp ym debbarg dna pu tas I
”.ssa ruoy no talf llaf uoy semit ynam woh ees dna liat a tuohtiw dnuora gniklaw yrt uoY“ .dias fieL ”,nam
”.semitemos eno sa drah sa tsuj s’daeh ruoY“
”?siht si htap hcihW“
”,pam eht kcehc ll’I“ ”?regnol hcum woH
.boj ecnarusni ym ta
.thginot ecno deid tsomla I“
.noonretfa yadsendeW a fo elddim eht ni krap a ot gniklaw saw I ereh tub