.derewsna I nehw neppah ot detcepxe evah dluoc I tahw wonk t'nod I
ta ti rebmemer ot evah neve t'noD .rebmemer I tnemom tseduorp ym t'nsaw tI
.stneidergni hserf seriuqer taht dna
,ylneddus dna emag elttil sih no pu kcip ot nageb I ,yllautnevE .em rof
.seitnewt dim ym ni saw I emit eht yb os ro derdnuh a hguorht enog ylbaborp d'I
.enuJ ni nepir ot meht rof tiaw ot emit evah ton thgim uoy
,aliov dna ,gniniamer tnemides yna evomer dna rehtegot lla ti ritS
.tuo rehctip ruoy dah ydaerla evah dluohs uoy ,tniop siht yb ,woN
,sseug I dna ,ecnis reve rehtegot neeb ev'eW
!htnom a rof pu ti teg t'ndluoC
:srewsna owt evah I taht ot dnA
.elpmis ytterp s'ti
.kcirdneK dna em no ni deklaw rehtom ym nehw rehtegot dekcol erew selzzum ruO
.rof gnikool er'uoy tahw dnif thgim uoy
!ereht syawla t'nsaw ruf ym ni yerg ehT
ereht saw ti tuB
,taots rehtonA
.eert a ni gnittis ociR dna ruhtrA" ".hsurc
.sgniht niatrec rof epoh t'ndid I fi
nwod deremmis ehs yllautnevE
,syaw detrap ew dna detaudarg I retfa nevE
.hguone naht erom neeb syawla sah retnec tnemniatretne ym no DCL hcni 54 ehT .gnitool trats ot erac yllaer t'nod I esuaceb
.nameltneg tcefrep a ton m'I os ,thgirla ,thgirlA
.ecnereffid ega eht tuoba denrecnoc erom saw dna
".mih ta gnikool erew uoy yaw eht was I"
.derahs ew ssik taht noitnem ot ton ,llew ,dna ,hO
,namow detanoinipo yrev a saw ehs
deredliweb elttil a em gnivael
”ecileF ruhtrA yb edanomeL eerF-raguS ot ediuG elpmiS A“   yojne esaelP
.ti fo yna rehtaf llet t'ndluoc ylniatreC
.gnol siht dnuora gnikcits rof sknahT
.ti tuoba ylsseltneler em edihc dluow dna taht fo devorppa evah ton dluow ehS
sekatsim strap emoS
.sseltrihs deb ym no gnittis saw zehcnaS kcirdneK nehw
.enola etunim a dah ew revenehw ti tuoba em dlocs dluow ehs dna
a dnemmocer d'I neht ,dlo sraey neves ton er'uoy fI
.ni ttub d'eh ,yug a htiw gnittahc saw I fi tub ,ffo skcor sih tog tahw onnuD .htiw pu kooh ot gniyrt saw I yob yna dna em neewteb-ni teg ot dekil erus eh dna ,eno dah I fi rehtorb ym rof nekatsim neeb evah dluoc ylbaborp
.elihw a rof …su neewteb ti tpek dna eniw eht ot pu ti deklahc eW
,em naht redlo sraey elpuoc a saw eH
,hguoht yllufknahT
dna pots-non em desaet yehT ".eert
,ega ym saw ohw tibbar kcaj a ,ecurB saw erehT
gniyl eb d'I ,tuB
.nuf rof tiurf kcip ot yenom gniyap tuo yddig gnieb sreeuq su fo hcnub a ,seY
.elcitra eht etirw llew sa thgim I ,ydaerla diap neeb ev'I ecnis ,lleW
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
,eci emos dda ,rehtegot lla ti ruop tsuJ
.pu sgniht ekahs ot dnuora gnimoc
.dab ylralucitrap
.mih morf syob gnilaets eno eht saw I
?taht ni nuf eht s'tahw tub ,erus ,flehs eht ffo wef a barg dna erots eht ot og ylpmis dluoc uoY
tog ti ,hguoht ,thgin enO
.loohcs hgih fo tser eht tuohguorht sseldneirfyob yltsom tfel saw I dna nosaes a detsal ylno gnilf tahT .hcum rettam t'ndid tI
.eb ot tuo em edam yeht sa hsiddig sa saw I ,llew ,saw I
.ylsseltneler trapa em erot sneeuq esohT
.em ot emac ociR taht thgin tsrif taht sa teews sA
,mih ees llits ew ,yllautcA
.edanomel eerf-ragus fo rehctip a dna em rof gnitiaw
,ksed ym nwod gnipiw nageb dna oot flesmih rof egnops a tuo delluP
"?serac kcuf eht ohW .tenalp eht tih ot tuoba si knabruB fo ezis eht dioretsa nA"
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
evif ot ruof dnA
.ssik a otni thgir em llup dna sdapwap sih otni elzzum ym poocs tsuj ot mih denigami reve evah dluoc I kniht t'noD
ym dah I tub ,ycips oot teg ot ton ,llew
.hsurc a tog s'enoemoS"
,seitriht ylrae ym ni saw tI  .did I wonk I
na saw ehs gniht yag eht saw ti ,tsrif tA
,tsael eht yas ot ,saw egroeG dneirfyob siH
.teerts eht otno tuo su delruh dna skcen ruo fo epan eht yb htob su detfil ,enirevlow gnikool ffurg a ,recnuob a nehw dedne ylno tI .sreksihw s'rehto hcae dellup dna ,swap ruo ta dettab ,rehtona eno pals ot detrats
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tnemom yrev siht ta ot pu era ecnerroT dna eh tahw rednow I dna
.rehtona ni roolf eht no sehtolc naelC .elip eno ni roolf eht no sehtolc ytriD .syob esoht fo eno saw I ,seY
.pu naelc ot erehw em gnitcurtsni detrats dna swap ym otni gab hsart a devohs eH
.setsat ruoy no sdneped rehtegot lla ti gnirb oT
nomel eht ,woN .noos laeR
.tellaw ruoy laets dna ecaf eht ni uoy hcnup
.laref a ekil rehctip a otni reneteews ruoy pmud tsuj t'nod uoy taht si ,no eerga dluoc I dna rehtom taht gniht eno s'ereht fi
,dah I dna trihs ym rednu wap eno dah eH
.edis rehto eht no uoy eeS
.eno thgir eht rof gnikool tuo og dna emit emos ekat ot evah tsuj uoy dna raey lla ecudorp ot dnet yeht
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.lerdnuocs eht etiuq sa debircsed eb dluoc ylbaborp ,lleH
,stih dnasuoht a revo toG
.no emit ruoy fo tsom dneps ot tnaw ot gniog er'uoy erehw s'taht os ,edanomel doog yna ot yek eht si
,oud suoived eht etiuq emaceb eW
.epicer eht ot kcaB
,lleH .ereh saw enoemos taht ees yeht
.werg rehtona eno rof sgnileef ruo ,rehtegot emit erom gnidneps detrats lesaew eht dna em nehw ,esruoc fo oS
.tiurf eht gnitcepsni dna gnitsiwt
”ecileF ruhtrA yb
.pu maet ot gnol os su koot ti eveileb t'naC .tteJ dna eM
.seitriht ruo ni erew sdneirf ym dna em kniht t'ndluow uoy ,yob hO
s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw
,otacsoM fo owt ro elttob a ffo gnihsinif retfa ,eciwt ro ecno ,ebyam dnA
.nem ot emac ti nehw ykcip t'nsaw ylniatrec I
,kcirt eht od ot snomel egral evif ro ruof tuoba dnif I
.mih dniheb ti desolc
.slacol emos teem ot detnaw dna aera eht ot wen erew dneirfyob sih dna mih yldesoppuS
sruhtrA rehto yna tuoba yrrow ot evah t'ndid I dna deirram tog ew ,taht retfa raey A
.tuo nrut lliw sgniht woh tuoba ro tuo denrut sgniht woh tuobA .yas
mih htiw deyats I
.etutitsbus eht dda
.taht kniht d'uoy ,lleW
neht dna gniliob retaw eht teG
,hguoht og I erofeB .emit eritne eht ociR otno gnidloh eb ll'I
.nettirw er'yeht nehw ton ,dedeen er'yeht nehw desaeler era dna ecnavda ni detcartnoc era yllausu sgniht eseht ,gnieb tsrif ehT
.adnelpS htiw ti ecalper ylisae
?knird a duts a yub ot yrT
,ognid emosdnah yrev a
.egroeG deman xof a ,emit eht ta dneirfyob sih htiw saw eH
.yad eht evas ot gnimoc anihcaM xE xueD etunim tsal yna s'ereht kniht t'nod I .eurt ton s'taht sseug I ,oN .diarfa ton m'I .og ot doog eb ll'uoy dna
.ti fo tsom eht edam I dna
,llew …sgniht hcraes ot woh wonk dna tenretni eht htiw doog
.rekihhctiH flowereW ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
sdneirf ym htiw saw ti tub ,uoy ot gniticxe yllufwa
,oN .tuoba esac ym no tog ehs gniht ylno eht eb t'ndluow tahT
mih htiw evael t'ndid eh sa gnol sa tsuJ
:sepicer emitremmus etirovaf ym fo eno uoy hcaet annog m'I ,yadoT
”ecileF ruhtrA yb edanomeL eerF-raguS ot ediuG elpmiS A“
.laidroc rehtar gnieb pu dedne ew ,lla ti etipsed ,dna ,taht retfa elihw a detsal meht fo owt ehT
.tnemom yrev siht ta evarg reh ni pot a ekil gninnips ylbaborp si mom ym ,woN
.edanomel eerf-raguS
rehtien ,swap sih ni owt htiw ereht saw tteJ
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.yob tsrif ym htiw em thguac ehs nehw
era uoy fi ,niagA .oot detnemucod llew yrev lla saw tI
.ysub sregnif eht speeK
.yawa mih laets d'eh ,flow ynroh toh emos htiw gnicnad saw I fI
.tawt a hcus gnieb rof ezigolopa
,tfel yltpmorp eH
,neht kcab dah I spukooh ynam woh no kcab kniht ot gnissarrabme s'tI
.no kcab trihs sih teg ot emit evah neve t'ndiD
,tenalp ruo yb pots sneila neerg emos fi taht epoh I
,syad wef a ni gnimoc dioretsa taht htiw ,yletanutrofnU
sdnuos taht teb I
.emit dlo yag a gnivah sdneirf ym htiw tuo
.yldnik mih deteerg I
.yllautca ,did reveN
.rood ym ot pu dewohs xof eht yad eht tegrof reven ll'I
hguone evlove aes eht ni hsifyllej eht taht epoh I
.sgniht fo edis reteews eht no eb ot enim yojne I ,yllanosreP
.revo syob yna dah I revenehw esuoh eht ni ycilop srood-desolc-on a saw ereht ,sdrawretfa ,yas ot sseldeeN
ecileF ruhtrA yB edanomeL eerF-raguS ot ediuG elpmiS A etoyoC triD yB
,gnieb ylbaborp tsrif eht elihw
siht dnif dna riaper nac yeht revres a s'ereht taht epoh I
.taht fo naf a etiuq ton
raguS rof stneidergnI
,od yeht nehW .elcitra
.dnuora loof ew did ecno reven ,yas ll'I ,woN
.pmor kciuq taht evah t'ndid ew ,oN
.ffo sessa rieht gnihgual dna taeper no ti gnihctaw sdneirf ym gnieb ylbaborp esoht fo flah
.stibah esoht peek I did
pu gniworg strap eroM
.sevlesmeht rof esu nac yeht epicer eno no tratsdaeh a evah ll'yeht
.hguone llew uoy od dluohs eno citsalp a ,ysmulc ylralucitrap tsuj ro neves era uoy fI .rehctip ssalg
,levon a gnitirw si
nac uoy ,epicer siht ni ragus yna gnisu eb t'now ew ecniS .purys elpmis eht otno ,sey hO
.emit ot emit morf pal sih ni daeh ym htiw tuo dessap ebyaM
.em htiw taht ekil sgniht od dluow taht loohcs hgih ym ni yob rehto ylno eht dna
.lla ta etepmoc ot deen t'ndid ew ezilaer ew did "?htob ton yhW"
.eromyna hsart revo gnippirt tuoba yrrow ot evah t'noD
.esle gnihtemos no wap
.noititepmoc eht etiuq saw eh ,yob ho yob ,dna pu dewohs tteJ nehT
.ssem eht etiuq saw I
.gnihton ekil spih eseht gniws dluoc diletsum siht tub
.egelloc ni saw I nehw slliks fo tsil ym no t'nsaw retaw fo top a gnilioB
.tesolc ym pu denepo ew nehw detniaf ylraen eh ,raewS .noitcerid ym sdrow eciohc wef a gnidda neht dna won yreve
retaw fo spuc ruoF :edanomeL eerf-
.yddub ,noos uoy ees ll'I
.ykcip elttil a eb nac I tub ,sevael ti etsat a s'ereht kniht I
.lla ta pu yats t'ndluoc eh ,yllautneve neht dna ,etal sa etiuq pu yats t'ndluoc eH
ot naem I tahw si ,deirrow ton m'I
.syawla rehtegot eb ll'ew
,yad s'enoemos nethgirb yllaer ll'taht gnihtemos ekam annaw uoY
,eert nomel emas eht htaenrednu sevlesruo dnuof eW
,ereht morf nwod delooc sgniht ,yllufknahT
.tuoba ittegaps ittespu dlo
.mih ot sgniht niatrec esoht fo emos noitnem I did
dna rood tnorf ym hguorht deppets eh nehT
.ti otni gnivid erofeb deb ym ffo hsart hsup ot gnivah
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
?ti eveileb uoy dluow dna ,pmor kciuq a rof revo mih thguorb I dna bulc +QTBGL s'loohcs ruo ta tem eW .epyt yssirp laeR .taht ekil gnihtemos ro ,rojam yrotsih a saw eH
.retaw trap eno dna reneteews laicifitra trap eno yltcaxE .od I
"?nepo er'yeht kniht uoY" "?eman sih s'tahW"
,elbbur ruo hguorht sgid enoemos fI .niaga revo lla
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.epuolatnac a ekil nepo god taht tilps ew ,thgin tahT
.sgniht tuoba tnew I yaw eht ton saw tahT
,hcrop eht no gnittis s'eh ,won nevE
,redrum ydoolb ekil demaercS
tsuj ew ,oN .gnitib liat elttil a neve ebyam dna ,sgnaf dna swalc ,gnihcnup dna gnikcik sevlovni tahT .thgif a ti llac t'ndluow I ?lacisyhp gnitteg bulcthgin a fo elddim eht ni staots tluda ssa-nworg owt ,enigami uoy naC
.ylkciuq degnahc snalp dna
.epicer eht lla uoy evael dluohs I sseug I
.purys ruoy tog ev'uoy
,ton ro ti eveileb ot esoohC
.em ot derettam taht lla saw
pu sgniht trats ot erutuf eht ni sraey dnasuoht derdnuh a retaw eht fo tuo pets ot
,seilpmi eman eht ekil dna purys elpmis a etaerc tsum uoy ,oN
,edanomel eht otno ,syawynA
.dias eb nac taht esle hcum ton s'ereht dna did yeht yaw eht deneppah sgnihT
.ecalp eht revo lllllla tog liat yM
.moor ym ot peekpu fo level emos mrofrep ot em rof saw pihsdneirf ruo ot noitidnoc eht fo trap dna sdneirf emaceb ew tuB .eciwt ro ecno ,j ydnah a ebyaM
.ton ro yug eht dekil I fi rettam neve t'ndid ti semitemoS
"?won epicer emitremmus a gnitirw uoy er'yhW .yraurbeF s'ti ,ruhtrA"
,noititepmoc emos llits saw erehT .evititepmoc ssel emaceb tteJ dna em dna
.em rof tfel stesnus gniniamer wef eht fo eno hctaw dna og I taht emit s'tI .em tuoba tib elttil a
.srebmun gnignahcxe pu dedne ew ,llew ,dna tsrif ta snoitasrevnoc llams saw tI
dlrow eht ni evol eht llA
,terces ruo emaceb tI
.em htiw tuo og ot detnaw llits eh ,kcis tog tteJ nehw nevE
dna su tuoba elttil a wonk dna yrots ym ees ll'yeht ,ebyam tsuj ,ebyam dnA
ot taeh eht ffo ti llup
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.seilppus gninaelc fo lluf teksab a htiw retal setunim net ton kcab emoc ot ylno
snomel dezeeuqs ylhserf
.dne yrev eht litnu
,deksa yksuh hsikniwt a litnu t'nsaw tub
?!?edanomel eerf-raguS
si rewsna dnoces ehT
dna gnir a mih evig ot reve naht emit retteb a si won sseug I
.no neht morf gnitseretni yllaer tog sgnihT
.esuoh eht fo tuo desahc yltpmorp saw ognid eht dna
lufeciov ylralucitrap saw dna ,saw ehs taht taots elbon
,ecaps nwo ym gnivah dna smrod eht ni reganeet a gnieB
,rellevarT wolleF ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.taorht ym fo kcab eht otni kconk sdanog ym tlef I ,drah os rekcep eht ni em deenk egroeG
.trat elttil a ti ekil od uoy fi neve ,thgie revo og t'ndluow I tub
,siht ekil etiuq ,gnirps a saw tI
.1202 fo yrotS trohS tseB
.tsrif nameltneg a m'I
.elihw a detsal tahT
purys elpmis adnelpS fo spuc owT eci fo puc enO
.setadpu erutuf rof
.flesym erolpxe ot tenretni eht fo yteritne eht dna snoitcaretni enilno wef a saw dah I llA
.ociR ym tem I taht
edanomeL eerF-raguS ot ediuG elpmiS A“ saw sihT
,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
.esuoh ym ot emac eh ,keew taht retal dna ,egroeG htiw ffo sgniht tilps dah eH
ni gnivil saw I etats eht waS !desufer eH
.elbatneserp gnieb no detrats em tog ohw
ll'taht edanomel a ekil emoS
.enilno oediv a dnif ot drah oot eb t'ndluow ti erus m'I ,sgniht hcraes ot woh wonk dna tenretni eht htiw doog era uoy fI .lla
.meht rof gnitiaw gnihtemos eb ll'ereht ,tuo emoc stnediser sti nehw dna sevivrus taht retlehs tuollaf emos eb annog s'ereht taht epoh I .hguoht epoh od I
,ylbaborp si dnim ruoy no gniht dnoces eht ,woN