delbmeser ti taht
.cangoc fo roloc eht dah dna
.esoper sih morf eicruM gnihcnerw yltneloiv ,edalg eht nopu llef teiuq gnivrennu nA
,sniev sih hguorht desruoc daerD
.snevaeh eht ni srats ekil erom dekool hguorht yaw sti dnuof thgilnus elttil tahW
,roloc nooram peed a ni deyd saw taht ebor gnol A
.nwonknu deniamer
.won naht redliw saw tserof eht nehw emit a fo sespmilg
,thgis s'eicruM fo egde eht ta deremmihs snoisiV
,thgil eht thguac ti nehw
ezeerb gnissap A
,kaeps ot demees tcnitsni peed A
.thgin eht etipsed thgirb gninihs
;deid ylneddus dniw ehT  .aes ytpme na no
.rorret gnilfits a dewotseb meht fo thguoht eht
.semit lareves deknilb seye sih dna
.deknilb seye eht
,seye rieht morf emac remmilg egnarts A
",dnoyeb efil retteb a si ereht uoy esimorp I"
.dnim sih otni derehtils thguoht lanoitarri nA  .gniyfirroh dna
.smra s'regnarts eht ni delbmert eh sa
,evoba sevael eht koohs
,arolf lacol eht ffo hgih timreh emos ylbissop
,sthgis sih otni devom yeht litnu meht fo wonk ton dluow eH
.roolf eht ot nwod yaw eht lla dehcterts taht triks a htiw
.dneirf raed a rof tfig neewollaH a si yrots riehT
gnihton od ot tnetnoc saw eicruM
tpada ot drah gnikroW
.seert eht hguorht gnippils thgilnus fo tfahs a ekil ,tnaidar dna tnelis emac yehT
.srae sih dehctulc eh sa
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.yawhcra na gnimrof seiponac gniniwtretni rieht
.edalg a ot denepo ylneddus
,snoisiv eht yawa evird dna yrt ot thgit seye sih tuhs eicruM  .tnemirrem ehtilb ni
dnim s’eicruM no flesti dekooh dna edisni deppils taht noisausrep a gniksam enot tnasaelp ehT
kcab gnillaf tnes saw eH
,stenrag ekil krad dna hcir
",latrom raed ,diarfa os eb t'ndeen uoY"
ti sserac ot nihc sih rednu wap a deppils regnarts ehT
,evom a gnikam fo lufraef ,llits gniniameR
ytilauq suonahpaid a htiw gniremmihs enot ylhtrae eht
.tnereffid yllohw snosaer rieht
.retnec eht ta gninepo llams a rof evas
rellirhs gnimoceb eciov sih ,dias eicruM
,srae sih ni gnislup ti raeh dluoc eh litnu
.larutan dnoyeb saw noisserpxe rieht fo lortnoc ni os enoemos ees ot
,dehcaorppa yehT  .elbram dehsilop
,seert eht sdrawot deklaw yehT  ".reverof
.yldrawkwa gnittuj eton a tuohtiw ylhtooms dewolf dnuos eht erehw semihc gnihtoos ekil
.sneerg nrobbuts dna der htiw dekcelf dlog fo emod a ekil saw tI
.enam yffulf a ekil tuo gniwollib
".ssilb tub thguan wonk lliw uoY
.erif lufroloc fo gnir a gnimrof
.elkcirp niks sih gnikam
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,elgae-daerps nwod dial dna retnec eht ot deklaw eicruM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.railucep eciov rieht dna ddo saw tnecca eht tub ,yltcefrep meht dootsrednu eicruM
,etihw yhsa na otni dedaf taht spit gnilruc eht rof tpecxe ,roloc ni kcalb saw tI
,latrom ,niaga em lleT"
.roloc-dlog fo sesiri tils htiw kni sa kcalb
.sesnes sih fo segnirf eht ta gniregnil ohce na ekil ,sdrow rieht fo egde eht ta elbraw tsethgils eht pu kcip dluoc eH
taht suorednuht os seciov htiw depoohw dna delggig yehT
,detrap spil dna denesool eugnot htiW
tlob ot regae saw eH
,lleps a rof seirrow ruoy tegroF"
denekciuq htaerb siH
.wap s’rehto eht dloh ot tuo dehcaer eH
,gnihtyna rof yrrow ron
"?latrom ,em htiw emoc ot ekil uoy dluoW"
.edis sih ta tser ot nwod gnippils ylsuoituac sdnah
,kciht etiuq saw kcen rieht dnuora ruf ehT .xof citcrA na
,tesnus eht ni maelg ot demees ydob riehT
.eracs a mih evig ot sdoow eht ni ksam a gnignah enoemos
.thgin otni yad denrut dna yks eht tuo dettolb ti kciht os yponac A
,desu ylerar saw koot eh htap ehT
,dellimdniw smra siH
”sdooW eht ni regnartS A“
.sesiri nedlog esoht ni gnilriws ylwols
.elbahcuotnu tsomla dna derednihnu deraeppa yeht ,yponac eht tsniaga dehsurb ylraen srae rieht fo pit eht sa nevE
.ecnabrutsid yna rof pu dekrep srae sih dna
erac ym rednu eb lliw uoy rof
,nosaer a dnif ron llacer t’ndluoc eH
,tirips sih otni peed delioc taht rewop a gnitrexe ssenpeed stI
.deksa regnarts eht
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
"?eman ruoy si tahW"
.yzoc dna etaciled
.devom yeht sa mra s'eicruM fo htgnel eht gnola nur wap rieht gnittel
,mih nopu saw regnarts ehT
enif dna etihw os ruf htiw
.sroloc gnitallitnics fo thgis a saw
taorht sih ni thguac htaerb sih
.smra rieht ni eicruM gnildarc
,ruf nworb sih no deggans sgiwt dekoorc elihw sehtolc s'eicruM tsniaga depsar sevael degde-rozaR  :ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  A_retirW yb ”sdooW eht ni regnartS A“   yojne esaelP
,dennirg regnarts ehT
eveirper emoclew A .selbuort sti fo flesti ytpme dna
decalp ti elihw regnarts eht tsurt ot mih denokceb tI .dnik dna eltneg
,ti fo wenk mih tub esle eno oN
.deunitnoc eicruM ",detseretni ton m'I ,gnihtemos lles ot gniyrt er'uoy fi ,nam ,kooL"
;ees dluoc eh lla saw ecaf s'regnarts ehT
".sdoow eseht decarg elpoep ruoy evah yleraR
.etum emaceb sthguoht sih dna
sevael eht dniheb deppils seye ehT
,ydde na ni thguac neeb dah eh fi sa saw tI .seye
.aitreni mlac a otni sthguoht sih dellul
neht ti ees t'ndid eh fI
.noob a eb ot taht dnuof tab eht tub
delbmeser ecaf rieht ,esolc pU
.rediw gninway tserof eht fo ssenpeed eht
,srae sih ot gnimrahc saw ti ,sselehtenoN
.regnarts eht ot eman sih evig yleerf ot erised a
,noisiv sih dnoyeb erew taht sgnihT
was eh sgniht eht tub
yks eht gnirucsbo yponac gnipeews rieht
,yawa spets wef a koot dna teef sih no kcab eicruM thguorb yehT
.modnaf eht ni gnilbbad ylwols yrruf ecivon dna retirw tsiybboh a si ohw ,A_retirW yb
.dnuorg eht ni ssennevenu na tsniaga deggard leeh s’eicruM
.egrahc ym emoceb dna
,yrautcnas dehsirehc sih saw sihT
.thgiliwt gnidaf eht ni remmihs meht gnikam
,revewoh ,htap netaeb eht ffO
,deklaw regnarts eht sa ria eht ni derettulf yehT
".latrom a rof eman lufrednow a hcus
.elbisneherpmoc deredner saw taht
.tnemevom sih ni noitatiseh a saw ereht tub
.krad eht ni gnimaelg sgnaf rieht
.efil citceh sih fo srednimer meht htiw thguorb elpoep rehto fo ecneserp ehT
,ylevisolpxe emac tceffe ehT
,dnoces yreve htiw rekciht gniworg
.daeh rieht fo pot eht no sreltna fo riap eht saw egnarts tsom saw tahW
.noitanigami dnoyeb erew
.thgin dloc eht otni tuo gnillips
.ecnaraeppa s'regnarts eht yb dexifsnart dna tops eht ot detoor flesmih dnuof eh
.esle erehwon og dluoc seye sih
reduol worg ot demees traeh sih fo gnitaeb ehT .no hcterts ot
seveels nepo sa devres taht htolc fo shtgnel erew sredluohs rieht morF
tfirda dnim sih dnes tub
.snoitome fo doolf a ni dnim sih gninword airohpuE
.emac reven tcapmi eht tuB
.llits tnew seert eht
.ruf sih ta gnippin citats ekil ,gnilgnit mra sih tfel hcuot ehT
.ees thgim eh tahw deraef mih fo trap A
,tsrif sruoy em llet uoY"
,dessim saw gnihton taht os ylwols dnuora dekool eH
,rewsna on saw erehT
.tnerap rieht tramstuo ot deganam ohw dlihc a ekil yddig mih gnikam ,snoitome sih delkcit thguoht ehT
htaerb sti dleh emit erehw
,detsaw won saw epacse sih rof pu tliub dah eh ygrene ehT
egnarts erew taht sehtolc erow regnarts ehT
.seye gniyrp morf ti delaecnoc egailof nworgrevo eht erehw sdoow eht ni terces elttil sih ot ,yad retfa yad
.hctip eht ot ecnaifed ni raelc enohs seye eht teY
.dias regnarts eht
.niatrecnu dna ,erusnu ,tsol os tlef eH
,A_retirW yb ”sdooW eht ni regnartS A“
.ecaps dna emit ni yaled a tub
esnetni os yoj a
.ecaf sih no elims a htiw dewollof eicruM dna
.noisiv sih gnirucsbo dna seye sih revo gnillaf ti fo tfut a
,yawa dedaf yad eht fo seiromeM
?pleh ot ereh erew yeht ebyaM
,decnad dna mih dednuorrus smotnahp ehT
.reviuq htaerb sih dna
.lufhctaw dna trela eb ot mih gninraw
.erusaem dnoyeb sgnisselb dna stfig htiw uoy rewohs lliw I
.evom ot denilcnisid erew sgel sih tub
eman siH  ".eicruM ,esaelP"
seert gniyaws fo naorg eltneg eht dna sevael gniltsur fo ecneibma navlys eht
.srrub kcodrub ekil
sisats fo stekcop erew
.ti derehtoms dna
.ecaf enitsirp rieht derutcarf htrim ,taht tA
evom rieht edam regnarts ehT
"?eman ruoy si tahw
.sredistuo ot gnimoclewnu dna dliw
N"  .enaw ot detrats tnemtnahcne ehT
llits dnim sih tel dluoc eh ereht nI
.denrut saw kcab sih elihw mih gnihctaw
.draeh eb dluoc sevael gnihcnurc ron ssarg gnipsar rehtien dna ,dereviuq ylerab htworgrednu ehT
.tnaillirb reve deniamer regnarts eht
.worb sih ot taews dloc a thguorb dna
deunitnoc taht ecnelis esnet eht dna seye gniknilbnu fo riap eht ylno
tnaw ton lliw uoY"
htap sih ot kcab mih werd syawla teef sih yhw saw tI  .hsuh eht ni
edalg eht gnicarg reven sllaftoof sih
”,latrom a teem ot si ti egnarts woH“  .dehsinrub neeb dah ti fi sa demaelg ti dna
nus gnittes dna yponac tserof ehT
.cinap s'eicruM yb derehtobnu ,dias yeht ",latrom ,niaga uoy ksa I"
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ecaparac s'elteeb a fo ecnecsediri ylio eht ekil
.mih ta gnirats seye fo riap a dettops eh litnu gninrut dna gnihctaw tpek eh teY
.snoitome rieht deyarteb hctiwt ro esaerc elgnis a toN
maercs ot deirt eh sa
traeh sih fo gnimmurd eht ot denetsil eh
hsurb eht erehw tops a dehcaer eh emit eht yb yks eht ni wol gnuh nus ehT
,teY .moolg gniworg dna thgilnus gnildniwd eht htiw gnihsinimid sroloc sti
.xulf ni reverof tnemnorivne na ot tcaer dna
.regnarts llat a deklaw tuo dna
.gnimoc ruoy erofeb dnal eht dessentiw dna ,srats eht fo yaws eht nees
.emoh morf yawa emoh a
.esor cinap sa
.derebmuls dlrow eht dna
,yerg nrut ot demees dlrow ehT
.senob sih ni gnitarbiv ti leef dluoc eh
,pit mih tel ot tnetnoc dna erew yeht erehw detooR
,mih revo emac mlac detcepxenu nA
,saw ti revetahw ,tnetni riehT
,taerter ytsah a ekam ot deirt eh dna ,eicruM eltrats ot hguone saw tI
.mih dehcuot regnarts eht nehw tnelis nellaf dah daeh s'eicruM ni eciov nekcirts-cinap tahT
,sklis fo deb a ni gniyl ekil saw ruf rieht fo leef ehT
.sdrawpu gnihcaer sehcnarb rellams htiw
smotnahp lufroloc erew sllah navlys tsav esoht neewteb gnileehweerF
",eicruM"  .mih erofeb ytuaeb eht yb derutparne oot ,sgninraw eht deeh regnol on dluoc eH
,gniraelc eht delcricne seert llaT
.enecs eht yb dexifsnart doots eh sa seye s’eicruM dethgiled tI
,gninrut syawla erew dnim sih ni sraeg ehT
,dnuos tnasaelp dna hsul a htiw delkcuhc erutaerc-xof ehT
,ytilaer ot kcab mih dekcohs noitanimluf neddus a ,nehT
,llews ot demees regnarts eht dnuora ecnecsenimul ehT
.yromem sih otni sevlesmeht deraes ycnarbiv rieht dna
".esle enoyna nees reven dna ,semit fo not a ereh deklaw ev'I ?ecalp siht dnif uoy did lleh eht woh dnA"
seenk sih ot gnispalloc
.eicruM ta gnirats llits seye egnarts rieht
.gnar llits yrlever fo sdnuos eht tub
,traeh sih ni dekauq noitome lamirp dna tneicna nA
.ekahs ydob dna ecar traeh sih edam ti taht
.taebtraeh sih gniwols dna yteixna sih gnilleuq
,gnisluvnoc traeh sih tnes cinap fo tloj A
.reyal peed-elkna na htiw dnuorg eht deteprac dah meht fo tnuoma doog a tub
laer meht gnikam
.snoisufnoc laicnanif rieht dna stneilc htiw gnilaed
,daerps swodahs eht edam
.seye gnirulla dna ruf enif rieht htiw eye eht ot gnisaelp etiuq saw regnarts ehT
,srettirc gnitib dna stnalp suonosiop fo yraw
,eicruM"  .hteet ekil-
,emac yeht sa ylkciuq sa dedaf snoisiv ehT
,teef sih no kcab teg ot elbmarcs dam a edam eicruM
.ekops regnarts eht
,repmihw ylno dluoc eicruM
.etaminani sa tsuj dna nialecrop ekil htooms ecaf rieht
,eicruM rof ti dednetxe dna wap nepo na desiar yehT  "?mlaer ym oT"
;dlrow tnednelpser a otni wodniw a hguorht gnireep ekiL
.ydob sih morf gnieelf noisnet
evloser sih ta dekconk taht mhtyhr suoronos a
,stessa gniugolatac ,srebmun gnihcnurC
.detemmulp traeh sih dna
.wolloh gnignir eciov
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”!gnihtemos yas ,tuo em kaerf ot gnitrats er’uoy ,kool-
.skeehc sih no demoolb htmraw railimaf A
eicruM ",wonk t'nod I enoemos ot enim evig ot tuoba ton m'I
.htrae gnivomnu eht tsniaga mals daeh sih leef ot deraperp
.sgniw remassog fo eicruM gnidnimer
,regnarts eht ta kcurtsbmud derats eH
,sdworc dna esion fO
rieht no desucof flesti dnif syawla dluow ezag sih ,erehwesle kool ot thgim eh sa yrT
.noitcudorp fo tnerruc sselesaec eht
,yltnelis mih dedrager erutaerc-xof ehT  .dias
.gniraelc eht otni deklaw dna
.eciov ylnevaeh taht htiw erom ecno dekove saw
.htrae eht nihtiw peed morf htrof gnilbbub retaw ekil
,snoitareneg ruoy fo sseltnuoc rof seert eseht fo edahs eht rednu deklaw evah ew roF" .dias yeht
,enasni sa nosrep eht etirw ot ydaer neeb dah eH
esle gnihtemos deciton eicruM dna
,nmutua eht otni etal gnieb ti etipsed no gnulc ylnrobbuts sevael riehT
;thgit seye sih tuhs eH
yponac detluav eht htaenrednu gnikcilorf
.gof eht otni hsinav efil dlo ruoy tel
.yllis os demees lla ti
,eciov lautca s’regnarts eht gniraeh t’nsaw eh fi sa saw tI
,regnif elgnis a htiw keehc sih dekorts ti erofeb wap derruf-etihw a htiw kcab tpews saw riah siH  .dias yeht
.teem dluoc seye rieht taht os ecaf sih pu thguorb yltneg yeht erofeb
,tnemssarrabme htiw hsulf ot tuoba erew skeehc sih sa tsuJ
.xetrov eht sdrawot mih gnidiug tnerruc eht
eman sih raeh ot tub derettam esle gnihtoN
,ecaf s'regnarts eht no werg nirg A
,eicruM ni werg noislupmoc A
.yrruh sih ni trid dna sevael pu gnikcik
.sevael fo retsulc ymoolg a ni deltsen erew seye ehT
.enog raf saw taht ecnalab emos niager ot citnarf
;egde eht dnoyeb dessap eH
.tuo pils eman sih tel ot ydaer saw eh
,ekops eh "…t'ndluohs-hs I …on-
.regnarts eht morf dluoc eh sa ecnatsid hcum sa tup dna
delbmert dnah sih tuB .reffo eht ekat ot regae saw dna dnah a desiar ohw
,nepo deppans seye siH
,knarp a saw ti kniht ot detrats eicruM
,ti fo trohs deppots yeht nehw gniraelc eht morf yawa pets a saw regnarts ehT
.lla retfa htnom taht saw tI
?suoituac os mih edam taht regnarts eht tuoba ti saw tahW
.ewa htiw ediw seye dna kcals waj
,stiw sih derehtag ylwols eH
.tnecifingam os eno yb derettu
,pirt eht htiw derehtob evah t'ndluow ynaM
.tsixe t'ndid ylpmis ti
.sgniw sih ot emac mrah on erus gnikam naht rehto dnim elttil meht diap eh tub
eciov renni sih revo dnah lufecarg a
sroloc rebma htiw srebme ekil wolg seye esoht was eh erows eicruM tub ,thgil eht fo kcirt a neeb evah dluoc tI
,deifirret dnoyeb saw eicruM hguohT
.sesnes sih gninekawa
,thgis eht ta enips sih pu lwarc revihs a leef dluoc eicruM
.niaga noitcartta egnarts taht tlef eicruM dna
eugnot ngierof A
.llew eb dluow lla yawa deklaw dna nwod daeh sih tpek eh fi ebyaM
,esnetni erom werg ylno yeht tub
.thguoht ni syawla niarb sih
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.diov eht ni rats enol A
,riah sih debrutsid dah llaf eht sa gnihton ees dluoc eH
.ot yvirp saw eh ylno egdelwonk dlotnu na
seert owt eht neewteB
.ssima saw gnihtemoS
saw sihT     .niaga reve
,eye s’dnim sih ot erew yeht hguoht sselmroF
L“  .ylbeef tuo kaorc ot ylno
telcric a delbmeser taht epahs a otni daeh eht dnuora deniwt dna worb s'regnarts eht evoba morf werg tI
.eman sih derettu yllanif eh
,ecaf sih no nwad eht ot nika tcatnoc eht dnuof eH
...su htiw gniyats ekil ot emoc yam uoY
"?eman ruoy si tahW"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,rehto hcae sdrawot nworg dah taht seert nawor owt ees ot dnuora dereep eH
eldeen laever ot kcab dellup spil
.teef sih ot delbmarcs eh ,tsehc sih ni gniremmah traeH
.netrohs ot demees reven taht sksat fo tsil yrdnual A
,htap rehtie nwod mih gniggut traeh sih ni gninraey ehT
.wenk yldrah eh enoemos htiw yldneirf os eb dluoc eh tsahga
.dias eicruM ”?olleh …hu-
",latrom ,noitseuq taht uoy gniksa eb dluohs ohw ew si tI"
.noitarebrever eht ni dediser suorbenet gnihtemos tuB
taeh htiw elkcirp ecaf sih gnikam
.meht dniheb gniwolg
.yponac nmutua eht dloheb ot drawyks dezag eh sa seye sih morf yawa riah wolley fo tfut a gnihsurb
,erofeb nees dah eh yna ekilnu erew yehT
U“  .depmuj ron demaercs rehtien eicruM ,elcarim emos yB
,kcals og sbmil sih tlef eh dna denetfos dnim siH
,lufhtuoy reve dna tnarbiv
.sdoow eht rof etairporppani tub ,etisiuqxe dna
.luos suortsul s’regnarts eht ot ti gnidnib
.yltsohg dna lufecarg stnemevom rieht