.sdrac eht ni saw tuokrow ecin a fi
.ydeerg oot elttil a tlef ti tub
”.ti od ot gnilliw era uoy revewoh ,meht kcil ,meht ffins ,teef ym egassam ot uoy ekil d'I tub ,em ot wen rehtar si sihT“
taht mih dnimer ot tnatropmi osla saw ti
,noitnetta sih dedeen taht sisirc ronim emos htiw laed ot thgin eht otni etal krow ot dah eh nehw ekil
.deilper rednaxelA
.erusaelp dna ssenisub xim ot gnilliw erew wef a dna
,hcuoc sih ni nwod tas dna pu gnuh eH
,yako saw ti fi wenk
.ylkciuq derewsna ohw ,eneguE dellac eH
.os ylbatrofmocnu ton tub ,thgit saw tI
.flesruoy tneserp ,haeY“  deksa eH
ohw retirw gnimoc dna pu na si ohw ,htooteriD AKA ,mmirG flokarD yb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.nettik doog a s'erehT“
dna eneguE ta ssap a edam d'eH
,ylidaer dewollof rednaxelA  ”.em wolloF“
,esae decitcarp htiw taorht sih otni peed ti gnikat
,gnidnamed dna mrif saw eciov s'eneguE
.mih ta flesmih nworht yllacitcarp dah
.rentrap moordeb sih ot noitnetta lluf sih evag eh
rrup detnetnoc a tuo tel eH
.siht no ni lla gniog saw eneguE ,hO ”.mrofinu ni
fo kcal a morf semoc taht detsuahxe fo dnik eht saw rednaxelA
,ecin sih ni esuoh sih ot pu dellup eH
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.snoitcerid elbatiforp erom ,retteb ni ynapmoc eht reets ot sgniteem hguorht tis ot dah eh nehw ekil noitsuahxe latnem ro
?netraM renael ,rellams eht gnidnammoc regiT ralucsum ,gib eht ni ereht saw nuf tahW
,od ot gnilliw t'nsaw rednaxelA gnihtemos saw ereht fI
,llew sa yag erew ffats sih fo emos
dna ffo rehto hcae deird yehT
,tnemtnioppasid fo egnit a htiw deton eh ,teef saw hcum sa mih eticxe t'ndid tahW
,deilper eneguE ”.esruoc fO“  ”.nuf dah I
,tekcaj tius s'reltub sih denottubnu ylwols ,ylluferac rednaxelA
”.knird etirovaf ruoy no pu kcots ot erus edam I“
.parts hcae htiw dekcilc hcihw
lamron sa no deunitnoc dna
sih ta deppin yltneg dna dekcil eH .trihsrednu eht
.taert a sa ,yojne uoy gnihtemos s'ti fi ti od ll'I tuB“
”.ylimaf ruoy htiw emit ruoy yojne esaelP .neht ,yadsruhT“
,detailimuh tib a ,detanimod ylhguorohT“
,relevarT dlrowrehtO eht fo dnegeL fo eman eht
.enohp eht revo raelc saw eciov s'semaJ
,dednammoc eb eh taht hguone ylpmis t'nsaw tI
,mih erujni ton ot sa os ylluferac ,ruf s'eneguE hguorht swalc sih nar eH
”.no nrut a t'nsi ffuts toof ehT“
,htooteriD/mmirG flokarD yb
,nettik ,no ralloc ruoy tuP“
gnihtemos draeh eH
”?ris ,gnihtemos deen uoy oD“
,sediseb dna ,won thgir mih tseretni t'ndid esicrexE
.xes fo thgin a otni denrut
”?ris ,gnileef uoy era woH“
”.deifsitas yletulosba tub
.rellevart wollef ruoy
,dnim t'ndid eh detats eneguE hguoht
.meht htiw gnitrilf ,dibrof sdoG
htob yeht os ecalp ni metsys a dna degnahcxe seigolopa lautuM
.nirg a htiw deilper rednaxelA
”.syaw rehto ni flesym yojne dna esuoh ym ni tis ot tnetnoc ma dna yad gnol a dah evah I
.ti ot noitnetta gnirb t'ndid rednaxelA dalg saw dna
dna nwod stnaprednu sih dna meht gnikat ylwols dna
edamer ylhserf sih no dial rednaxelA  .tfel eh
,thgirb saw nus eht sa yag saw eh wenk mih rof dekrow ohw enoyrevE
.taht od dluoc eh ,yadsruhT  ”?yadsruht yas
,diputs gnihtyna od ro hcum oot knird t'ndid eh erus ekam ot dnuora neeb dah eneguE dna
.naelc teef sih tpek
”.rednaxelA si sihT“
.eciov ssab ,peed sih ni derettum eH ”.haN“
,rellevart wollef ruoy
.kcab sih htaenrednu gnihtemos eciton ton ot hguone desirprus ton tub
.mih fo egatnavda gnikat saw eh ekil tlef yltsenoh dah dna
.dootsrednu saw sihT
.tnavres a fo sdnammoc eht gniyebo ni laiceps gnihtemos saw ereht tub
.ffo rehto hcae denaelc yeht erehw
.eman a ot eciov eht ecalp ot deirt eH ”!xelA ,yeH“
”.tuo sgniht emos tset
.detailimuh eb dluow eh ,saw taht sa elbissopmi ,won thgir ni deklaw mrif sih morf enoyna fI
otni dna dnuora tnacirbul gnibbur sregnif s'eneguE tlef eH .gnitiaw dna
.gninrom siht desicrexe ydaerla d'eh
.derised eneguE sa noitnetta hcum sa meht gnivig dna meht gnigassam
.esir ot nageb kcoc sih dna
tnemom a rof msilanoisseforp eht gnippord
”?ris ,esle gnihtyna ereht sI“
.hctorc s'reltub eht dnuora ruf eht gninaelc
”?gnihtemos deen uoy did ,xelA ,hO“
”.rolehcab a llits er'uoy dna bulc pirts a ot gniog er'ew ,nom'C“
.dedda eH ”.em repmap
”.sey sdoG ,hO“  .deksa eneguE
dna erom ekat ot mih gnihsup
-eracretfa fo trap sa punaelc eht htiw detsissa eh -deb
,tenretni eht fo tnevda eht htiw dna ,elyts cissalc eht deyojne syawla dah rednaxelA tub
.gniteem a etaitogen dluoc yeht ,doom emas eht ni osla saw rehto eht dna doom eht ni saw meht fo eno fi taht gnieerga
.revihs eneguE gnikam ,dap eht ssorca eugnot sih depsar eH
,erofeb ralloc a nrow reven dah rednaxelA
”?erom evah ot tnaw uoy oD“
'.siht tuoba gnikniht pu dekrow flesym nettog ev'I ,sey yas
.flesmih ot ytreporp eht no ecalp nwo sih evah ot derreferp eh hguoht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.deb eht otno nwod mih gnihsup
rehtegot decaf rieht gnignirb
edis ot edis ti gniyaws
”dnaH tnanimoD ,gnortS A“
-tsaisuhtne rac drah-eid a saw ohw ta dekrow eh mrif eht ta sevitucexe rehto eht fo eno yb 'rac doog a'
,semit fo tseb eht ta tihs fo seceip cibohpomoh erew yeht gniredisnoc
.nuf hcum sa dah t'ndah dna erofeb ecivres laiceps eht deirt d'eH
,nuf eht htiw ecnemmoc ot gnitiaw dna
,detnioppasid yldlim ,pu gnuh eH
mih dniheb dehcaer eneguE ”.esaelp
.ni dils ti erofeb retcnihps sih tsniaga pit eht tlef eh neht dna ,elohssa sih
,rednaxelA htiw troppar yldneirf a pu tliub dah dna
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,demmar gnieb flesmih elihw ssa eht ni semaJ mar ot ekil eb thgim
”?huh ,revo enoemos tog ev'uoy os ,hO“
.duola desum rednaxelA
.gnixaler llits ylekil
,eneguE ,uoy knahT“
-are nredom eht otni devivrus dah noisseforp reltub eht
saw sihT     ...peelsa llef dna
-ecnerrucco nommoc a ton -thgin eno knurd neeb d'eH
”?laiceps ro ,ecivres dradnats a eb siht llahS“
.sdnah sih gnissik yltneg dna
gnileef mih evael did noitamriffa fo kcal a
.noitpo na osla saw eneguE tub
.dehtaerb eneguE ”.hguonE“
.eno evissimbus erom eht gnidloh
,deooc dna nihc sih rednu dehctarcs yltneg eneguE
-desuba dna desu leef ton ot regiT eht rof tnatropmi saw tI
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.revo ylimaf evah ,hu ,I“ .dias semaJ
,ssa sih detneserp dna deb sih otno delwarc rednaxelA  ”.flesruoy
d'yehT .rehtegot thgin rieht
htiw flesmih niatretne dluoc eh ,llew ,ton fI
,tius deroliat ,ecin a yb denroda erew hcihw
.lla sih ti evig ot gnilliw saw eh os ,mih ot wen saw sihT
-boj eht fo trap a ton dna ,stluda gnitnesnoc owt neewteb nuf ylpmis saw siht
.moordeb sih otni dna sriats eht pu
,si reffo ruoy hguoht gnitpmeT“
,nwod dnuow eneguE ylwols dna
.oi.sapaT no detsoh
,nepo rood kcab eht draeh eh nehw dna
.srotaderp rof dekrow reve ylno
,noitcudorp a ti edam eh ,ffo sehtolc sih ekat ylerem t'ndid eH
thgin esnetni tsrif rieht litnu dootsrednu t'ndah rednaxelA dna
”dnaH tnanimoD ,gnortS A“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
seugaelloc sih ot hcus timda d'eh taht ton ,etarucca erom saw rolehcab demrifnoC
,sredluohs ralucsum sih dellor dna rac sih fo tuo tog eh sa ,derednow ylfeirb eH
noitsuahxe lacisyhp t'nsaw tI
,ti gnola eugnot sih depsar yltneg dna hctorc s'eneguE ot denruter eH
-hctorc sih elzzun yltneg ot tnemom a rof tsiaw sih ta gniregnil
.os od ot gnilliw naht erom saw eneguE dna ,detanimod eb ot detnaw eh
,nuf fo sthgin rehto dah
.ysae ylriaf saw setsat sih dehctam taht eno gnidnif
,ylgnisirprus ,eneguE
,teef htob ot noitnetta lauqe gnivig ,deunitnoc eh os
,daeh sih no sdnah s'eneguE tlef eH
,osrot dna smra desopxe
dekcuf gnieb eno eht eb ot derreferp eh ,llitS
nuf eht s'erehw ,tuB'  .ot evah t'ndid eh deerga saw ti
noitsuahxe fo dnik tnereffid a tlef eh ,woN
stnap sih gninottubnu ,tsiaw sih ot esor rednaxelA dna doots eH  ”.ezirp
.nuf fo thgin lanoisacco eht htiw
esaelP' .eit sih gnitsujda ,deilper rednaxelA
.detsuahxe saw rednaxelA
deyojne dah dna tnazingoc ylluf neeb dah eh
,dias dna eit s'rednaxelA fo dloh koot eneguE
togrof eh -rac yecirp yllauqe sih dellup dna
nuf neeb dah thgin eht taht deerga yeht
,sirroM ,yrros m'I“  '...s'ti
.gniog peek ot animats fo dnik thgir eht dah eneguE dna
,ni-evil saw eneguE
detseuqer yllacificeps dah eh taht sevolg etihw fo riap a gnivomer
.noitnetta tpar sih eneguE evag eh sa thguoht rednaxelA '?taht ni
a rof doom eht ni erew uoy fi gnirednow saw I“
,xamilc flesmih tlef rednaxelA
,tneps saw eneguE litnu dewollof ylregae eh
,tuoba suoicsnoc-fles saw eh taht psil thgils a dah eH
,mih deticxe seye yrotaderp esoht gniees taht rednaxelA dlot ecno dah eH
,dekcuf ylsuoicsnoc yeht emit tsrif eht desserts dah eneguE ,tnatropmi saw eracretfA
.mih ediseb deb eht no dednal ralloc A
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,tnemom eht ni saw ti sa nuf
,srotaderp rof krow ot derreferp seiceps yerp taht epytoerets a saw tI
.thgin taht derebmemer ydobon lufknaht saw dna ,gniknird enog d'eh emit tsal eht derebmemer eH
.detats rednaxelA ”.nuf fo thgin
.mih rof ti deniatniam ohw elpoep eht dna
,no ti tup ylreporp ot woh uoy wohs nac I os emit txen yalperof eht piks nac ew ,raeg rehtael erom evah od I“
,ralloc eht deggut tnemevom hcaE
htooteriD/mmirG flokarD yb
.mih gnikcuf demuser dna ralloc eht ot
.desimorp rednaxelA ”.emit txeN“
rednaxelA ”.uoy ot pu ti ekam ll'I .knird ot doom eht ni ylralucitrap ton m'I tub
”.noitaercer elttil a rof doom eht ni erew uoy fi gnirednow saw I“
”?hguoht ssenrah dna hsael tahT
,gnizigolopa dna mih fo egatnavda nekat d'eh gnikniht semaJ fo yromem eht ta delims eH
flesmih ot ecalp elohw eht ,sdik on ,esuops oN
.deticxe gnitteg saw eh dna tey detrats neve t'ndah eneguE
,eit eht emac neht
.ffo skcos eht dils ylwols dna ffo seohs sserd sih dils yltneg rednaxelA
eh esiwrehto tub ,spihc nroc
,ti no dellup dna hsael dedis-elbuod eht debbarg eneguE sa yllaicepse ,egnahc siht deyojne eH
”.aedi dab a ton s'taht ,yllautcA“  .desaet sirroM
.ksum fo egnit a htiw
.erofeb decneirepxe d'eh gnihtyna ekilnu hsur enilanerda na thguorb
.sknird emos htiw tnuocca grubsillE eht gnihsinif gnitarbelec era srehto eht dna em tub
eno siht piks esaelp
,ylniatrec ,cimanyd rieht saw taht ,sruoh krow lamron gniruD
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.dekan uoy tnaw I ,em rof pirts ,woN
ro peels ot tnaw tsuj uoy fi niatrec yleritne ton
,tsehc sih dnuora ssenrah rehtael a fo sparts eht dellup dna
,dlohesuoh eht no gnidneped tcirts sa t'nsaw edoc sserd eht
ot uoy tnaw I“ .delims eneguE
”.thginot ton tub ,gnitpmeT“
,cimanyd siht ni delever netraM eht
eno gnorts eht sa rednaxelA htiw emit siht ,deb ni deldduc
er'uoy erehw ,noitalumits lufgninaem
.ni degagne yeht xes lausac yleritne saw ti fi neve ,laiceps erom elttil a gnihtemos saw ti ,meht roF
,tuo dekael tahw pu dekcil eH  .tnemom eht rof
,netraM eht rof dna ,desserped
,ti gnidlof dna ti gnivomer ylluferac
.stneve s'thgin eht decsinimer yldnof dna
.edom lanoisseforp erom a ot gnippaws ,deksa eneguE
.dellup gnieb ti tlef dna kcilc
.lworg suoroma na evag eH
.lla retfa ,erohw a ekil gnileef ekil t'ndid eh
.saedi diputs yllaer ot enorp saw eh ,knurd yllaer nehw dna
,msilanoisseforp sih detaicerppa rednaxelA
.yaw eht fo tuo elttil a gnihtemos od
,eneguE desuora ylniatrec gniod saw eh tahw tub
.guns fo dnik thgir eht tsuj tlef ti ,no ti tup eh nehw dna
,reltub sih fo ydob tif tey ,nael eht gnirimda
,etarucca ssel saw noitciped nommoc eht
.elbaitogen-non t'nerew sdnammoc wenk htob yeht tub
.deilper rednaxelA ”.dradnatS“
,emoh rof dael ydaerla uoy dias dleiffehS“
.reporp esuoh sih deretne dna pu gnuh eH ”.nuf evah uoY“
derrup eH  .deneppah dah
.mih deticxe taht dnA
,pu llits saw eh detacidni wodniw eht tuo ecnalg kciuq A
fo tnecs eltbus a saw ereht ,hcnets elbirroh a elahni mih ekam ot hguone leurc t'nsaw eneguE
deredisnoc saw ti tpecxe saw ti yllacificeps tahw
.noitatirri sih edih ot level dna tfos eciov sih gnipeek ,deilper
ydaer ydaerla ,tcere
.emitnwod sih gnirud neve
.deilper rednaxelA ”.ris ,seY“
yb levon bew gniogno na gnitsop neeb sah dna ,noitcif tluda sih detsop yltnecer ylriaf sah
”?ris ,nigeb ot ydaer uoy erA“
,gnizigolopa saw ohw rednaxelA saw ti ,gninrom eht ni ,dna decseiuqca
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
rewohs eht ot mih gnikat
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
hsael eht fo dne rehto eht deppilc eneguE
.hguone thgit tsuj ti dleh eneguE sa
.enohp eht hguorht elims eht raeh dluoc rednaxelA ”.ris ,esruoc fO“
.pu meht gnidlof esiwekil
,drah gnikcus nageb eH
-kool reltub lacissalc eht fo tnemyojne s'rednaxelA otni gniyalp
”dnaH tnanimoD ,gnortS A“   yojne esaelP
.ylpeed ni dehtaerb dna daptoof s'eneguE otni eson sih deirub eH
.tnurg dna naom eneguE gnikam ,eugnot hguor sih htiw tfahs eht desaet rednaxelA
,yltrohs evirra lliw I“
,ris ,seY“  .deksa eneguE
,thgiR' .taht no dael eht saw ohw rebmemer ot deirt eh ,tnuocca grubsillE ehT  ”?detseretnI
ssenisub nwo sih deganam renedrag ehT .semaJ dellac dna enohp sih tuo dellup eH .desum eH ”?nuf rof revo eneguE ro ,semaJ etivni I dluohS ...mmH“
”.erofeb neeb ev'ew naht rehtraf siht gnikat er'ew
,ssik etanoissap ,toh a rof
”.em eticxe ,ylwols ti ekat dna ,em sserdnu woN“
.tnempiuqe esicrexe evisnepxe sih dedrager ylfeirb eh dna egarag sih otni
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
-wob lamrof a htiw dna delims eneguE
s'tel ,rof eludehcser ot gnilliw er'uoy fi ,tuB
.ezirp ruoy mialc yam uoY“
”.thginot gnihtemos yrt ot uoy tnaw I“
,ekil meht ot gnihtemos od d'eh diarfa eb thgim yeht taht ,rehtar ,mih ot taerht a eb d'yeht thguoht eh taht ton
.weiv otni devom reltub siH
.gnikrims ,mih dehctaw eneguE elihw lausnes dna wols
.deilper rednaxelA
dah gniknird fo thgin a
,feileb ralupop ot yrartnoC  .syot emos
gninialpxe mih yb dewollof
.seohs sih ot rewol nwod dna
,spil sih neewteb gnippils eugnot
'.hsael a ,sdoG ,hO' .hsael A
,doohrobhgien yecirp tahwemos
.ytirecnis etelpmoc etacidni ot
.derewsna eh dna gnar enohp siH
”.thginot em gnigludni rof uoy knaht dnA“
debborht traeh sih
.daeh pmad yldlim llits s'eneguE dekcil yltneg dna
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
ti tahw tuoba thguoht eH
,ytlas ,taews saw erehT
desiar liat ,ylgnisaet
.emac eneguE sa gniwollaws
.dekil rednaxelA ekil tsuj ,gnidnammoc dna tnagorra ,elims tahT
.dias rednaxelA ”.gnitiaw eb ll'I“
.erom tnaw rednaxelA edam gut hcae
.gninnirg ,dedda rednaxelA ”.ris ,seY“
,tcere ylluf kcoc sih ,dekan doots eh nehW
,llew sa ralloc a gniraew eneguE ees ot desirprus saw dna kcab sih no yal rednaxelA ,wen saw sihT ”.kcab ruoy no ,thgirlA“
.ylthgils os reve tsuj nwod gnitib netraM eht ,tsap yaw sti gnihsup nwo sih