.eromyna ti yned ot elbissopmi …saw ti esolc sihT
.tnelis yal sepip eht dna won mraw saw tI
.mih ot kcab gnihtyna naht erom devol eh nam eht gnignirb ot yek eht eb ot ti gniveileb ,semuf eht rof denraey traeh siH
.xof a ,rebmulp eht ot dias samohT
.niaga yrt dna puorger ot ,retaw emos rof emiT
”.ereh efas ton era uoy dna
,dluow syawla uoy
.ecalp eht revo lla ssalg fo sdrahs llits erew ereht dna roolf eht no gniyl llits saw eH
ssarg eht no sselnoitom tlenk regdab eht
,deggurhs eilrahC ”?woH“
.aedi dooG .yako ,seY“
,enog si ydob ym hguoht neve ,rebmemer tsuJ“
ytefas ruoy si srettam tahw tuB .taht wonk I“
,dluoc reven uoy dias yeht sa neve
”.yaw rieht no era edagirb erif ehT“
.ti gnillif dna gnimossolb ,gnidliub eht otni deruop thgilnuS
.deksa regdab ehT
.edisni kcab gnidaeh dna rood eht gnisolc erofeb ,dellac samohT ”!od lliW“
.yawa kool t’ndluoc eh tub ,niaga hctiws thgil eht rof hcaer ot deirt dna demaercs samohT  .ereht neeb syawla d’eH .oN .emac ssenkrad nehw ylwols evirra t’ndid eH .weiv otni edaf yltneg t’ndid erugif s’eilrahC
”.flesym fo lortnoc tsol I
.ereht ni rehtegot tnemom rieht dah dah riap eht emit tsal eht morf dehcuotnu yal tI
.deddon eh ,yllaniF
ti yas ot detnaw syawla ev’I
.edisni kool ot denrut eh dna mih fo retteb eht koot ytisoiruC
.dednuop daeh siH
,yakO“ .kniht ot deunitnoc samohT  .gninruter saw yllanoitar kniht ot ytiliba s’samohT tuB
”.yllaretil mih ekat t’ndid
.liomrut renni sih yawa nevig dah ecaf s’samohT ylgnimeeS
,emoC“ .denialpxe tar ehT
.tlah tpurba na ot emac emiT .detiaw eH
,seenk sih ot deppord eh
”.esuoh eht draug lliw I
ekil em dleh uoY“
,edistuo tnemevap eht otno tog dna sdnuorg ronam eht tfel regdab ehT
.yawllah eht fo tuo deklaw dna desserd tog eH
?em htiw ereh tuo yats esaelp
,erugif s’tar eht hguorht hcum sa ees t’ndluoc samohT
ll’uoY .ereh tuo efas er’uoy ,thgirlA“
.tcnitsni no daeh sih koohs samohT
.mih gnieb ti fo yromem on dah eh tub
”.won sneppah tahw wonk uoy kniht I“
.knalb dniM .derettab ydoB
,flesmih ta nwod dekool neht ,esuoh eht otni kcab dekool regdab ehT
.enohp eht ot kcaB
”.tey emit ruoy ton s’ti ,hcuot ruoy evarc dna rof gnol I sa hcum sA
rebotcO teews a nO“
,ti tuoba lla togrof dna knurd dnilb tog
.rodirroc gnol taht sdrawot degdurt eh ,ylwolS
,pleh rof enoemos llac ot ydaer ,enohp eht ot pu gniklaw fo elcyc a deretne eH .elbuort peed
”?morf ohw ,hO“ .dias regdab ehT
.esruoc fo tsohg snas
.rehtegot daeh sih teg ot deirt samohT
.daeh eht fo ekahs a evag neht ,tnemesumeb htiw
”…thginot smra esoht ni em dloh
.erom gnihton dna yromem eht dnuora depparw gniyal smra
,yvaeh saw traeh siH .dias eH
.rorret s’regdab eht fo erawa ylgnimees
.enohpyap a dnuof dna teerts eht pu nar
”.hcum os uoy knaht ,tnecifingaM“
.esuops sih morf meht edih ot stsirw sih otno sraet emos depiw samohT
,nehctik eht morf retaw fo ssalg a detcelloc regdab ehT
.oga sraey esoht lla rof nellaf dah regdab eht
…I tirips ni em htiw eb syawla d’eh dias dnabsuh ym nehw
.tsrif ti did taht eno eht eb ot dnabsuh sih detnaw reven evah dluow eh dna ,yrc dluoc taht tsohg a fo draeh reven dah samohT
”?I did ,tfel ylurt reven I
”.ereht ni gniog uoy tnaw t’nod I tub ,ti xif ot pleh teg nac uoY
.ecalp ni dnuob saw eH
tnemurtsni eht detaoc
”.emit tsrif eht uoy esol ot drah os saw tI“ ”.os diarfa m’I“
.dnuow nepo na ekil
,ot klat ot detnaw eh nosrep eno ylno saw erehT .gniklat naht reisae saw gnihtyna ,drah erew eseht sa hcum sA
.taefed ni dias samohT ”.thgirlA“
.erehT .eilrahC .kcilC
,moor denaelc ylhserf sih ni devirra samohT denaelc ylhserf A
.detlusni tsomla ,deksa eilrahC ”?yhW“ .deksa samohT
”?llems taht s’tahW“
.deb eht morf debmilc dna delbmurg regdab ehT
.meht llif ot dnapxe ot regae dna ydaer htob sgniht ynam era ereht dna
.eilrahC ekil flesti deirrac neve tirips ehT
,ereht ni neeb dah enoemoS
.derepsihw samohT ”.laer ton
.kniht ot deirt dna
”.reliob eht s’tI“ .deplug regdab ehT
.ylpmis dias eilrahC ”.daB“ .tlah a ot gnimoc ,deksa samohT
reviecer eht no kcab enohp eht werht eh ,enod ecnO
yalp dna ereht tis dluow samohT ,semit retteb nI
.deb ni derrits samohT
',thgiN rebotcO teewS A‘ erahs emoC
.saw tsohg s’eilrahC lufrewop ssel eht
.retaw dna ssalg fo sdrahs eht gnissim yllufknaht
.gninrom taht ylwols ekowa regdab ehT  –  .tuo
.erom ecno mih ynapmocca eciov s’dnabsuh sih raeh dluoc eh ,yalp ot nageb eh sA
.rood eht morf ertem a tuoba tlah a ot gnimoc
.redloc emaceb ecalp eht yad hcae dna reduol werg ti yad hcaE
”.ti eveirg ot kaew ton s’tI
.meht leef t’ndluoc samohT tub
edagirb erif eht rof laid kciuq a edam eH
.krad saw gnidliub  ehT
.sraey 03 fo trap tseb eht rof etam sih neeb dah tar ehT
.eilrahC saw tI …seye sih ni kool eht ,eciov eht ,smsirennam eht dah eH
ria thgindim eht ni taolf sdrow eht gnittel ,ecnelis ni yletelpmoc tas samohT
,edis sih yb esuops sih fo htmraw eht tuohtiw dna seitfif-dim sih ni woN
,moor onaip detsud ylhserf eht otni deppets eH
”.evitom ym ot retnuoc era uoy ot ycamitigel ym evorp ot stpmetta yna ,raed yM“
.taes a gnikat dna loots eht tuo gnillup
og sgniht fo tol a tel dah samohT
”!ooooooW“ .smra yltsohg sih desiar neht
.ta kool ot raeb t’ndluoc llits eh secalp emos ,esruoc fo moor onaip eht toN .sgniht wef a gnitsud ,pu gniydit yb flesmih tcartsid d’eH
,peed ni saw eh ,dnabsuh daed sih gnitanicullah saw eh fI
,htap sih ni ria eht brutsid t’ndid stnemevom siH
trofmoc ot tuo gnihcaer ,nwod tlenk eilrahC
,ytpme niamer ton od secaps ytpme tuB
?emoceb dah esuoh eht tahW
”.ti desuac tahw gniwonk tuohtiw eid ro denosiop teg sklof tsoM
”.laer eb t’nac uoY“
,doow eht otno nwod mih gnimmals dna esiwekil gniod sgel sih ,gnispalloc eciov sih ,depsag samohT
.nihtiw morf gnimoc ruodo etinifed a saw erehT
.denruter gnilbrag eht neht dna ”-oT“ ”?tahw oT“
.regdab eht sdrawot deklaw ylwols tirips s’eilrahC .mih erofeb
,thgin rebotcO teews a nO“
.dnik ni did tub lla dnim s’samohT
.yawa gnippets dna teef dloc gnitteg neht
dekcalb samohT ,thguoht lanif ,eno taht htiW
.rood tnorf eht ot devom riap eht sa denialpxe xof ehT
…lleW“ .deplug samohT
.ecnereffid eht eb dluow taht spahreP .seye sih ni peels erom elttil a spahreP
.deipucco saw ecno taht tnacav tfel ecaps a ,htaed yb deitpme ,esuoh A :roiretnI ,enecS
,raja tfel saw rood ehT
.drah nmad oot deirt d’eH .detaefed eb ot tnaw t’ndid eh dnA .detnaw eilrahC
.deggeb eilrahC ”!esaelP !oN“
.tirips eht fo ecnaidar lacitsatnaf eht morf yawa derewoc thgil ylhtrae llA .llat doots tar eht fo tirips etihw thgirb ehT .deb eht fo tooF
,pu denaelc retaw dna ssalg eht htiW
”…ton er’uoy on ,on …oN“
.em liaf t’ndid uoY“
erugif eht no dexif seyE
,ruf sih hguorht delffur ria dloC
erom emaceb tirips eht
,tcefrep etiuq t’nsaw ecnedac eht ,gnidrow ehT
.spsihw ni yawa gnipeews neht
,syawla sA   .goD fO tsohG ehT dellac noitatneserp neewollaH laiceps a fo trap sa
.thgin ysaenu rehtona ekil dekool tI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
tahw s’tI .gnorts eb ot dah eh ,ti rof denraey tug sih sa hcum sa taht wenk eh dna
.eilrahC ot gnikool neht ,rood eht ot kcab gninrut ,dias samohT
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.teef sih ot desae ylwols neht ,tnemom a llits deyats samohT  ”.og tsum ew
,llems eht morf yawa saw eh rehtruf ehT
.ni yllufecarg knis dna
,thgir tsuj smra esoht ni em dleh
yticapac cilbup a ni mih fo hcum nees yllaer dah enoyna emit tsal eht saw larenuf ehT
.aedi retteb ,thgirlA“ .dias eH ”.yako
”…thgir ti ekam ,esaelp
.dluoc ti erehw swodniw eht hguorht deruop thgilnooM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.peels emos gnitteg ta troffe sih dewener samohT ,gnihtyna tuoba enoyna ot kaeps ot deliaf llits gnivah ,thgin tahT
.deilper eilrahC ”.esruoc fO“
.evisehoc ssel werg sdrow s’eilrahC
.psarg fo tuo pils sgniht fo tol a dna
.mih ta kcab dekool tar eht sa ecaf sih nwod gnimaerts sraet ,plug rehtona koot regdab ehT
si yrots s’yadoT
.niaga delims dna kcab deddon eilrahC
.deddon neht ,derednop tsohg tar ehT ”?ecalp siht evas
,yawllah eht nwod gniklaW
,gniliec eht ta pu ylknalb derats regdab ehT
,sdrow ekil leef t’ndid tI
.nav reh ot edistuo gniklaw dna gninrut ,dias ehS
.ecalp siht evael ot uoy deen I“
,dluoc nam rehto on
nac I yaw emos ereht sI“ .deplug samohT
,efas uoy tnaw I .uoy evol I“
diviv erom emaceb tsohg s’eilrahC ,sriatsnwod detagivan riap eht sA
.mih ta ylevitisiuqni gnikool saw eilrahC taht deciton eH
,yal ecno dnabsuh sih erehw dnuora smra sih tup ot ssorca dellor neht
”thginot efas emoh ti edam raed yM
,emoh em ekat emoc oS“
.mih dellif tcilfnoc
”?yako ,ylraluger gnikrow era smrala OC eht taht tset ot rebmemer tsuJ“
.thgin ta raeppa ot demees ylno yeht dna
,elihw a rof yltnelis doots yehT
.htaerb peed ,peed a koot samohT
ekil em dloh uoY ,nwad remmus a
.emit laer ni detcader gnieb saw ti ekiL
,yltruc deksa samohT
,eilrahC no tceffe na gnivah yletinifed saw llems sihT
eh ereh terces a saw erehT
.seye s’rehto hcae otni ylpeed derats riap eht dna
?emoceb dah eh tahw ni emahs eht ro ,mih gnittespu fo thguoht eht ti saW
.pu naelc dna pu burcs a ,ruf eht fo mirt A .eno gnol ,gnol A .rewohs A
”.reliob eht ffo nrut dna ereht ni kcab og ot tnaw I“
.sepip eht no trats daeh a teg ot redro ni
dna erugif sih hguorht ylhtooms dedilg smra sih tub
,ni deirram saw eh odexut eht gniraeW
tesolc sih otni dehcaer samohT ,dettif reliob eht htiW
.ronam eht ni moor rehto yreve tuoba tsuj ot naelc peed a evag eh tuB
.moor reliob eht dehcaorppa samohT sa
.ria hserf dehtaerb regdab eht erom eht
”.dluoc I fi emit tsal eno ecaf ruoy ot
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy
.skeehc sih nwod gnippird sraet ,dettimda eH
.gnuts seye sih raelc os noisiv A
.rood eht tsap pets ot devom eh sa dednuop daeh ’samohT
.efas ton s’tI“ .daeh sih gnikahs ,dias tar ehT ”.oN“
.pots lla d’ti ,naelc ecnO
”.ysae eb ot gniog saw siht dias ydoboN
.niaga deddon eilrahC ”.tnemtraped erif eht ekil ,enoemos llac dna enohp a ot og eW
,eciffo tsop a fo kcab eht ni ytivitaler derevocsid ohw
.deedni elap yrev
.wonk I“ .derettum samohT
yeht ekil niaga s’dnabsuh sih fo ezag eht gniteem erew seye sih fi sa ,onaip eht morf pu dekool samohT
,seceip ot llaf esuoh eht tel I …naem I
.enohp eht debbarg dna
.traeh sih ni tsallab eht yb ecalp ni derohcna ,rood eht edistuo deppots eh tuB
,ria dloc eht otni dehsinav yllaudarg tar eht fo erugif eht sa peew dna don ylno dluoc samohT
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.seirots neewollaH gnidaer er’ew keew siht dnA
?yas eh dluow tahW ?llac eh dluow ohW
.mih tih ti ,eulb eht morf tlob a ekiL
.skcart sih ni daed deppots eh
.regdab eht htiw nwod gnileenk ,dias eilrahC
.seye yltsohg s’dnabsuh sih otni pu kcab neht
.gnimaercs deppots regdab ehT
deddon tar ehT .denialpxe samohT
.seceip lufituaeb noillib a otni derettahs dna roolf eht ot llef ssalg ehT
.deraeppa eh diviv erom eht ,tog eh resolc eht tuB
tsud fo reyal kciht A
ekil em teerg uoy ,nrom
tahT“ .niaga skeehc sih nwod pird ot gnitrats sraet ,deddon samohT
.gnicar dnim dna gnihca ydob
.ti gninigami neeb evah tsuj tsum eH .derevihs eH
”.won og tsum eW .ecalp dab ,llems daB“
.lla saw taht ebyaM
.deb edam sih otni debmilc dna sehtolc nrow-yltrams sih fo tuo deppils eh
,ria hserf fo htaerb yreve htiW
ti draeh samohT tub s’eilrahC yltcnitsid saw tI
.yltnelis gnivom ,deb eht dehcaorppa eilrahC
.oga sraey esoht lla htiw evol ni llef I nam eht llits
.htrof deppets tar eht fo erugif  ehT
”…thgir em was taht hcuot ruoy saw’t
.was eh tahw gniveileb yletelpmoc ton llits
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.pu flesmih gninaelc yb emit erom pu desu neht eH
.seye ’samohT otni kcab thgir derats dna doots tirips s’eilrahC
”.efas eb ,raed ym eybdooG“
.noisulli na eb llits dluoc ti fi derednow eh
”.edixonoM nobraC“ ”.-s’ti ,decalper reliob eht teg ot enoemos deen uoY .gniyas saw I tahw s’taht ,seY“ .deddon eilrahC
,ylwols pu doots eH
.deddon dna deplug eilrahC
,won gniyrc saw tar ehT .hguone esolc tub
eldniwd dluow erutarepmet eht thgin ta tub ,yad eht gnirud melborp a t’nsaw tI
”thgiN rebotcO teewS A“ saw sihT     .oga
er’uoy ,evol I nam eht llits er’uoY
.noisulli diviv ,diviv a saw tI
gnilrad raed yM“
,emit tsal eno dnabsuh sih guh ot tuo dehcaer samohT
”.uoy gnisol revo tog reven I“ .deirc samohT
.nus gninrom eht ni detaropave ylegral dah retaw ehT
,ssarg eht otno dna edistuo tar eht dewollof regdab ehT  .laer eroM .dilos erom gnimoceb
.uoy ni eveileb t’ndluohs I yhw nosaer a em eviG“ .deksa tar ehT ”?I t’ndluohs yhW“
.ti ni onaip eht htiw moor eht morf gnimoc eb ot demees neve eciov s’eilrahC
.debrutsid neeb dah ti fo pot eht no tsud eht taht gniees
.saw eh ekil tsuJ
.ylteiuq dna yltfos dias eH
”?em ni eveileb llits uoy od yhW ?yhW“
.niarb sih morf deraeppasid ti ,ti draeh samohT sa noos sA
.sevlesmeht sllaw yrev eht morf gnimoc saw ti ekil
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,emoh em koot dna emac uoY
,ronam eht fo tixe eht ot srood eht sdrawot mih dewollof samohT sa dna
,yrev saw eh tub ,niaga tirips s’eilrahC deretnuocne eh ,edistuo ssarg eht no pU
.egap ytiniffaruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
od tahW“ .noisufnoc ni deworran seye s’eilrahC ”?deliaf …I evaH“
ria hserf eht fo htaerb peed a koot regdab ehT
.niaga yawllah eht otni dna moordeb eht fo tuo samohT del tar eht ,nwog gnisserd sih no tup dluoc regdab eht os tnemom a gnikaT
.dnuora hsarht ot trats dluow sepip eht dna
”.emoh ruO“ .dias eH
.mih ot kcab dekool eh sa tirips s’eilrahC dehcaorppa eH
,gnissim atad fo eceip a saw ereht fi sa saw ti
.laer eb t’ndluoc tI .laer t’nsaw tI
er’uoY“ .deb eht otni kcab desae ylwols samohT dna dilos dleh erats ehT
.moor raf a otni nward erew seye s’samohT
.gnineppah eb t’ndluoc sihT .gnineppah t’nsaw sihT
.enob eht ot revihs mih gnikam
tnemom a roF .detcilfnoc saw eh tnemom a roF
.delbrag saw esarhp eht fo dne eht tub ,nageb eilrahC
,onaip eht ta ni dekool samohT ,tsap deklaw eh sA
.ylpmis dias samohT
”.em fo diarfa ton eb ,samohT esaelP“
.oga sraey esoht lla mih decnartne taht elims taht gniraew
.thgis ni dne on htiw yad no yad esrow nettog dah gnibmulp eht morf gnignab ehT
”…dluohs syawla ti sa
,noitautis eht denialpxe dna
”.emoh ym si siht tuB“
.yal samohT ,erehT
.noitcirf tuohtiw ylgnimees devom eh
.srotceted edixonoM nobraC yna tuohtiw gnorw saw tahw tuo krow ot elba erew uoy elcarim a s’ti ,tsenoh eb oT .melborp oN“
.xut sih deveirter dna
.onaip dnarg a saw ti nihtiW
enotirab tevlev taht htiw gnis dna dnah ni knird ,pot eht tsniaga nael dluow eilrahC elihw
,redloh s’ti ni tas llits saw cisum teehs ehT
.devirra enigne erif eht sa
.ti deen d’eh decnivnoc t’nsaw samohT tub
.eilrahC uoy evol I“
”thgiN rebotcO teewS A“
”.efas ereh tuo er’uoY ?naem uoy
.taht ekil ton tub ,sey lleW“ .deilper tar ehT
.eroc eht ot bmun
”.srettam tahw s’taht ,hguoht efas er’uoY“ .derepsihw eilrahC
.mih dnuora etaroireted ot nageb devil d’yeht erehw ronam eht dna
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  lufraF lacsaP yb ”thgiN rebotcO teewS A“   .goD fo tsohG ehT ...no
.thgil eht ffo kcilf ot ssorca dehcaer eH
,yawllah eht otni kcab pets ot devom eh sA
.tsal ta dias eilrahC
.dias eilrahC ”.efas t’nsi tI
.llaw eht tsniaga kcab delbmuts regdab ehT
”?gnihtemos uoy ksa I nac ,netsiL“
”.lliw syawla I dna ,uoy ni eveileb I“
,mih rof taht tnaw t’ndid eilrahC wenk eh tuB
.peels laer yna teg t’ndluoc eh tub ,mraw yats ot dnif dluoc eh sa steknalb ynam sa rednu flesmih depparw d’eH
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.noitanicullah a saw tI
.nwod kcab ti ecalp neht
.dnim etarepsed a fo kcirt kcis A .lla retfa derit os saw eH
.dessap eilrahC ecnis emas eht neeb t’ndah eH
”…snaem taht neht tuB“
.eilrahC yb decnelis saw tub ,niaga detsetorp regdab ehT ”.won toN
t’nseod ,gniog er’uoy snaem
.yllabrev dna yllausiv htob ,tnerehoc
.gnar srae sih duol os ecnelis A
.esuoh yhtlif a fo tliug eht tsuj saw ti spahreP
.mih erofeb doots tirips etihw ,thgirb a sa ,eroc eht ot bmun ,derats eH
,tnew eh sa moor reliob duol eht tsap klaw ot gnideen
.niaga moor sih sdrawot dna sriats pu kcab og ot denrut neht
gnittes saw nus eht sa tsuj
”pleh elttil a dah I“
.t’ndid uoy rehtar dluow I tub ,seY“
.gnitteg t’nsaw tsuj
,yad eht ni reilrae deb ot og ot detcele eH
nrecnoc eht tsap hsup ot flesmih decrof eh ,lworg a htiW
.nehctik eht sdrawot tuo moordeb eht morf degdurt samohT sa gninefaed saw thgin eht fo ecnelis ehT
,hguot eb lliw emiT .hguot neeb sah emiT
”?em morf tnaw uoy od tahW“
”-ot pleh deen
”.dettif reliob wen eno s’taht ,neht thgirlA“  –
retniaf werg tsohg s’eilrahC ,kcohs sih oT
.tuoba erac I lla s’taht
.seye s’tsohg s’dnabsuh sih otni kcab derats eH
.yldlrowrehto eciov eht ,dias eilrahC
”.gnorts era uoy dna ereh era uoy tub
enim htiw traeh ruoy
.deplug dna deddon tar ehT ”?ti
”.uoy ni eveileb llits I ,enog m’I fi nevE“ .dias eilrahC
.ti yalp enola tel ,eromyna ti ta kool ot raeb t’ndluoc regdab eht dna
,regdab eht dnuora flesti gnipparw ria dloc
.egaugnal tnereffid yllatot a ekil ,tnerehocni ylrettu gnihtemos
,gnihtemos laid ot ydaer ,enohp eht pu kcip d’eH .teef dloc ,niagA .no sraey ynam siht yldab siht gniveirg eb llits ot gnitailimuh os saw tI
.esuoh eht ot kcab nar dna
.daeh sih koohs dna yltnelis dehgis eilrahC
sraey esoht lla dah
uoy dluow ,ytefas nwo ruoy roF
,sredluohs s’regdab eht no tser ot demees swap yltsohg ehT .mih
.tnemom a rof gnuh sdrow ehT
kcab derats xof ehT .dias eh
.ecno ta erehwyrevE .gnimusnoc llA
.dedeen eh tahw saw retaw spahreP