,noihsaf otni kcab emoc dluohs skaolc skniht ohw
.aes tesnus eht otni sknis tesnus erehW
.erehwyna ’nihtaerb er’yeht taht tseteews eht s’ti taht dnif ll’uoY
.nrae ot deen on ev’uoy taht uoy rof deraperp ecalp a s’ereh tuB
.nwo ruoy tub ssenisub on s’evol uoy ohw dna era uoy ohw dnA
.gnol si daeha daor ruoY .thgir lla eb ll’uoY“ dias nam dlo ehT
.nwod em dnirg dluoc dog on ,lufhtarw woh rettam on oS
.uoy rof ereht laem toh a s’ereht yrgnuh nileef er’uoy fi dnA
.deveirg ev’uoy enoyreve htiw detinuer er’uoy ereht siT
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer,floWcaM boR yb
.dnif ot decnahc I nwot a sdnalrevir eht ni erehwemos nehW dniheb tfel I daor ehT
.yadretsey fo nwot eht ot ereh kcaB yaw ruoy dnif yademos dna ,daor eht no kcab teg uoy nos oS
,nwonknu era nemecilop yadretsey fo nwot eht ni dnA
.sihTetorWohWyuG@ ,rettiwT no sekoj dab sih dna
em rof eno dna ,uoy rof ,ereht ’nitiaw s’taht ecalp a s’ereht dnA
.dog fo htarw eht erofeb nwod dewob tem ev’I nam a ynam s’tI .dort ev’I elim a ynam s’tI .em degnahc s’taht daor a ynam s’tI
.ti yojne uoy taht epoh I“
eerf s’ydobyreve erehT .snaol tneduts on ,sliaj on tnia erehT
,eud gnimoc tner on s’ereht yadretsey dellac nwot eht ni esuaC
,ereht lufecaep os dekool ti ecnis dnA
.ria eht ekat dna elihw a steerts eht klaw emoC“ em ot dias eH
”.tser a deen dluohs uoy fi ,elbatrofmoc tub ,dlo s’afos yM
”yadretseY dellaC nwoT A“ saw sihT
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.gnorw eb lliw me fo emoS
,”yadretseY dellaC nwoT A“   yojne esaelP
.aes revlis eht evoba sduolc tilnoom sA
.erofeb neeb d’I raews d’I .sthgil samtsirhc htiw tsuj til nwot A
egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”.yadretsey fo nwot eht nihtiW yats ot woh wonk t’nod yeht tub ,tisiv semitemos od klof gnuoY
..htimS niatnuoM eht
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw meop s’yadoT
,dessertsid eb t’nod ,daeh ruoy yal ot ecalp a deen uoy fi dnA
,erohs eht yb ti dnuof I sdnalrevir eht ni erehwemos saw tI
.nruter ot ydaer er’uoy erof uoy egnahc annog si efil dnA
.yadretsey fo nwot eht s’ti tahT yas ot referp I tub ,eman rehtona tog s’ti raeh I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.yadretsey dellac nwot a ot kcaB yaw ruoy no uoy sdael ti sa uoy egnahc annog si efil dnA
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil
.nos ,ereht ioH“ pu ekops eh dna em ediseb tas nam dlo nA
.aes teiuq a fo ffo tcelfer srats erehW em htiw thgin eht yats os ,gnol si uoy fo daeha daor ehT
meop s’yadot dna
.enog eb ll’uoy worromot :yadretsey fo nwot eht si sihT
.tsew eht ni saw dniw eht ,tuo saw edit eht ,nwod saw nus ehT
?eno siht ot del yaw ruoy ,dlrow eht ni secalp eht lla fO
floWcaM boR yb meop a
.tser ot nwod em tas I
.devaereb si ydobon yadretsey fo nwot eht ni roF
.nam dlo na ma I won dnA
.gnol gniyats eb t’now uoy roF
,floWcaM boR yb si
.nwot edisaes a thgil taht ,sthgil samtsirhc rebmemer I tuB
”.yadretsey dellac nwot eht oT ,yaw rieht dnif ynam ton‘s ,neht ykcul nikcuf er’uoy nos lleW
.ekam ot tey ev’uoy snrut ynam s’erehT