.deunitnoc yevraH
.niaga rehto hcae ta dekool corc dna xof ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,evirra ot tsrif eht erew tnecniV dna naJ
,etelpmoc snoissucsid eht htiW
,naicisum ,retirw a si ohw
.eelg taerg htiw yot wen rieht ta tnemesumeb s’maS gnihctaw saw ohw ,naJ ot revo denael xof elam eht
dluohs ew kniht uoY“
…woh fo erawa era stseug ruoy fo tser ehT“
.ytilibide s’ti nrecsid ot gniyrt nageb dna hsid eht dehcaorppa tser ehT
”?pu denil tog uoy ev’ohW“
”.noitaicossa s’renwoemoh eht fo doolb eht liob
”?ebab he ,pohs eht ni ti tif ot elba eb d’ew kniht t’nod I“ .detrats eH
tas erew eihctiR dna kcaJ erehw htoob eht ot revo riap eht derutseg eH
”~oot ti rof pu eb thgim yeht ,myg eht ta klof yhcnuar emos wonk I ,nuf sdnuoS“
”.tuoba deirrow neeb evah dluohs I doof eht saw ti on tub
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.reffo no gnihtyreve fo owt ro ecils a gnivah enoyreve htiw rennid lanummoc a gnimrof
.deggurhs esuom ehT
,repap fo stib htiw nwerts saw esuoh ehT
.gnihtolc dedracsid fo tnuoma riaf a dna
.noom elbaffeni eht
,deddon lerriuqs ehT ”.reggib
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”samtsirhC gnikcuF yreV A“ saw sihT
,esuom eht deksa eihctiR ”?ay era woH“
nevo eht rof launam eht daer dah maS
a strohs depirts-etihw dna kcalb fo riap a
.ti ssorca daerps won htolc
.tsil eht pu gnikcip ,detseggus yevraH
.esuom eht ot don gniwonk a gnivig neht ,ezag s’rehto hcae gniteeM
,daed ton elihw ,sklof ym dna samtsirhC revo elbat tnaig siht htiw kcuts er’ew ,oS“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.seugnot decnad yldi owt eht sa sdaeh rieht fo kcab eht gnittep yltneg xof eht
,mra sih rednu dehctulc htolcelbat ,moor eht otni deklaw yevraH sa dennirg maS
.delims yevraH ”~elttil A“
”?ssa s’enoemos ni tif ot gniog yllautca taht sI“
.flesti elbat eht dnuora nwerts yal sexob azzip eht dna
”.meht fo sdaol nevig gnieb peek I tub
.yltnulb deksa yevraH ”?odlid a ti sI“
”?neht txen s’tahW“
?dnim ni gnihtyna tog uoy ,snoitaroced ot noitaredisnoc tneced a evig dluohs ew gnikniht m’I“
,smret hcus ni tuoba thguoht nehw
.nrut rieht ekat dna nwod yal ot naJ gniwolla
”.ti lles nac eh os ti no ledom ot uoy stnaw tsuj eh ebyam ,hhs hO“
”.syaw elttil a kcab og kcaJ dna em ,lleW“
.tnecniV ta ylisaenu derats dna pu tas nooccar ehT
,decnuonna nexiv ehT
.hcneb eht no kcab gniyl ,detnurg tnecniV
,htolcelbat eht tog ev’I ,kool yeH“
.yb dluoc yenom taht citsalp tsepaehc eht htiw edam
,hcihw ecnetnes a ,dias yevraH
…gnitteg si og dluow ylimaf a erehw flug taht ekil leef tub pleh t’nac
”.eltbus yltcaxe ton s’tI“
.krims a evag maS
”.kooc ot woh nrael uoy
”.keew ddo na neeB
yhsitef“ …hhu a sa dlos saw tI
”.ni stnaw bulc knik eht morf enoyna fi ees dna ,kcaJ dna eihctiR ksa ll’I“ .deddon yevraH
””.rennid samtsirhC lamrofni
.aedi errazib dna drusba ,suolucidir ylrettu na si siht ,yevraH“
,tops yaw-eht-fo-tuo na saw tI
”.od nac I tahw dnoyeb tib
,deddon nexiv ehT ”.ti ekil d’I
.esuom eht ,deedni dna
,rehtegot derehtag dah naJ dna alegnA
,dehsilbupnu yltnerruc si gnitirw sih fo tsoM
”?kooc uoy naC“ .esuap
.eson s’revoR ot nwod ti dleh maS dna etalp a no decalp saw yekrut eht fo tucffo llams A
.nirg a htiw deksa maS
”.pup reh dna xirtanimod a wonk ot neppah od I ,lleW“
,ynam deviecer dah revoR
,nevo eht otni drib deraperp tahwemos eht gnihsup ,dias maS
.deddon neht ,htaerb peed a koot tnecniV
,kcab mih niw ot gniyrt yllautca ton er’uoY“
.yllacitsacras detnurg revoR ”!fooW“
,edis eht ot elbat llams a ta taS
,gnidliub wollahs tahwemos ,gnol a saw egatnorf ehT
.ruogiv eht fo ssel htiw
.rennid samtsirhC eht rof gnikam ta og a evah dluoc eh sehsid emos rehtegot tup ot deirt dah dna
,gnineve taht etaL
,xof a saw eihctiR
,rehtie snaem taht tahw wonk t’nod I“
.denialpxe yevraH
,llew sa elbaliava edam neeb dah segdab nuonorp fo noitceles A
.oidar eht no niaga revo dna revo dna revo dna revo dna revo deyalp sgnos 5 emas eht ,slaed eht
.mih htiw esolc pu gnittis xof eht ,deksa eH
tahW“ .noitom ”!ad-
.knat a no gnillup ,delkcuhc maS ”.skcuhs hO“
”.doof s’ti ,erehT“ ”?fooW“
deksa maS ”?suovreN“
.flow eht ta gnilims ,deddon kcaJ
?eert daed A ?sthgil giB
,luaP etisoppo alegnA
,tsetorp ni ti ni deirub efink egral
.detnurg dna elbat eht no swap sih tup yevraH
…dluoc I kniht ay’d ,foow tnew dna no ksam a tup I fI“ .dias alegnA
.ti lles ot yppah m’I ,yaw eht ni teg ot gniog s’ti fi ,kooL“
.lliw rieht fo trap sa ylimaf s’maS yb gniht siht nevig neeb ev’eW“
.sgab rieht nwod tas dna sredluohs rieht fo ffo wons eht dehsurb yehT
.tcerroC“ .deksa alegnA
”.neppah ti gnikam rof sknahT“ .delims yevraH
”~lerriuqs ,ereht ymmut ruoy no owt ro ba na yps I kniht I“
,thguoht dna yekrut opaehc ,ynit siht dnuof I ,llew ,seY“
”.gniht siht su nevig reven d’yeht hsiw sklof ym ekam d’taht gniht adnik ehT“ .dias eH
mih revo gniloord sraey tneps dah I“
.degnahc sevlesmeht tog tser eht elihw nehctik eht rof gnitraped
,stseug owt lanif ehT
”.step rof gniksa retsknik yldneirf a evah yam uoy os ,yalp pup otni si sdneirf s’yevraH fo eno kniht I“ .denialpxe maS
,dooh pup a ni etoyoc elam A
”?thgir ,worromot gnimoc er’yehT“
”.dah ev’I tseb eht si siht kniht I
.moor eht ot leef laivoj dna dexaler ,lufyalp erom a ,won nwod demlac dah ygrene ehT
,regguR PB yb uoy rof daer
.ylgnidaelp ylthgils ,dedda eH
,nehctik eht otni deggoj maS
ynam gnillup pu dne ot dnet t’nod
”.eihctiR htiw tog tsuj d’eh dias eh
”.esoppus I eciffo eht ni dnuora ksa dluoc I ,naem I“
,yevraH dna
saw maS fi ksa ot fi sa
.dat a sevren sih yrrac ot deunitnoc tnecniV ”.soggod ekil I“
.lavirra tsrif eht detiawa yeht sa ylsuovren rehto hcae ot delkcuhc riap ehT
”?no oG“ .dias yevraH
…hhu ton dna kcaJ htiw ecaps yxes a ni eb ot woh tuo gnikrow tsuj m’I“ .dias eH
.dekrims lerriuqs ehT
.setouq-ria gnivig ,dias eH ””lanoitidart“
,ffo raf t’nsaw rewsna tahT ”.drawkwa ti ekam
”.allenomlas tuoba deirrow erom tol elohw a tub
.nevo eht ta ylno gnikool ,deilper yevraH
.deddon stseug xis riehT .deksa yevraH
”.ytilauq latnemitnes evah yltcaxe t’nseod …tI
,wons fo kcal ehT
,teef ’ssertsim sih ta mraw pu delruc saw dna step ynam
elbatrofmocnu ti edam evah ot tnaw t’ndluow …I enif s’tI“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.delbmurg esuom ehT
.sllaw eht no sgniht rehto dna stneve reeuq rof sreilf
.rehto eht ni yawa ekat fo gab a
.rood eht ot pu deklaw esuom eht ,htaerb peed a htiW
brag xetal gnisopmi reh ni xof elamef eht
.demrifnoc esuom ehT ”ahctoG“
,etuc saw ti raey tsaL“
,kcaJ deman elidocorc a ,dnabsuh sih htiw gnola ohw
”.tsrif ti parwnu ot desoppus er’uoY“
”?uoy t’nod ,yekrut retfa thgir amene na evah annaw d’ydobon wonk uoY“
”?eihctiR dna kcaJ tuoba deirroW“
.moor eht otni dednuob yltpmorp revoR
.delims dna yltaen tas ohw
.nirg a htiw desaet eH ”.nuf on er’uoY“
.detsisni esuom ehT ”.uoy knaht ,oN“
.s’flow eht naht retrohs tib riaf
.daeh sih koohs yevraH
,dias esuom ehT ”.gib …s’ti haeY“
– .tnelis esiwrehto deyats dna
”.dnuora ksa dluoc ew sseug I tub ,dennalp gnihtemos evah ll’sklof tsom tcepsus I ,lleW“ .deddon maS
”.gnineve fo dnik rieht ekil smees ti
.stseug laitnetop tsrif sih dehcaorppa yevraH
,alegnA erofeb doots saw yevraH ,stnemom nihtiW
,elbat eht fo ertnec eht ni decalp neeb dah eert citsalp ynit A
,ygro na otni nrut ll’ytrap siht ykcul er’ew fi
.tnemrag enol sih ot gnitniop ,dias lerriuqs ehT ”?pot-
.sih dnuora mra na gnipparw
.xof sih ta dennirg corc ehT
,dias evah dluohs uoY“
,ti tuc ot gniog ton s’tahT“
.edis rehtie eerht fo swor owt dna dne hcae ta eno
”?kniht ay’d tahW“
atsap fo daoltekcub a ekam tsuj I ro ,slaem ydaer thgie su yub I
”?ereh er’uoy swonk maS“
.rehtegot tup d’yeht enecs eht fo sedis etisoppo morf rehto hcae ta delims yevraH dna maS
…ekil erom gnikniht m’I ,taht ekil toN“
,hhu os kcaJ rof sgnileef tog s’tnecniV tuo snruT“
.elbat llams rieht ot revo esuom eht gnidael dna ediw gninnirg ,delbbab xof ehT
.xof yldneirf eht fo erutan detraeh-yenoh eurt eht ksam ot elttil did tub
”?thgir ,smret doog no llits era kcaJ dna uoY“
”…hhu taht erom s’ti ,taht ton s’ti on ,oN“ .nageb maS
…I elbat siht evah ew won tuB
,os kniht t’nod I“
,tey toN“ .deksa maS
,staes rehto eht no gnimrof tsenevol suoromaylop dna emag oduL ynit eht tsap tperc dna pu tog esuom ehT
na toN“ .dennirg eihctiR
”.tnaw d’I tahw tsuj ekil sdnuos lanoitidart-noN“
,deraperpnu elidocorc eht
,rehto hcae ot ylsuovren tahwemos gnittahc erew riap ehT
,pohs eht ni metsys AP eht ta pu gnikool ,delbmurg yevraH
”.sevahebsim enoyna esac ni pihw a thguorb I“
”.eno enod ev’I
”?ecin gnihtemos flesahctog
.gnitae riap eht yb ylno detpurretni
.erutinruf fo eceip egral eht deye esuom ehT
”?emoh ta stneserp ruoy denepo lla uoy evaH“
,kcurt gnivom a morf ecalp ruoy rof gnihtemos gnidaolnu meht was kcaJ“
,tihs sa yduag s’ti
”.raey tsal naht regnol detsaL“
,euqisyhp ralucsum tahwemos llits tub rednels erom a dah yehT
.rood eht teg ot redro ni no kcab yesrej dna strohs myg sih dellup tnecniV elihw nehctik eht ni deniamer yekrut denrub s’maS
.desumeb doots owt ehT .dennirg eihctiR
.etoyoc dna nexiv eht ot elbat eht denialpxe dna
porc a tius dluow siht kniht uoy oD“
,gniht ”ssendrawkwa tiftuo yknik“ elohw eht tuoba won deirrow ssel m’I ,wonk’Y“
.”syadiloH yppaH“ htiw ffuts teg ylnO
”?uoy t’ndluow ,mih tsurt d’I“
”?gnihtemos ro tpoda ,ekil
.mraw peek mih pleh ot taoc nelloow sih tuo thguorb dah yevraH dna
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.detnurg esuom ehT
”.kcoj ym tsuj ni tuo krow ot evah ll’I dna taht ekil sgniht gniyas peeK“
”?uoy did ,doof god emos gnirb ot neppah t’ndid …uoY“
”…dluoc ew …hhu lleW“
na s’ehs ,deniart llew yrev s’eh ,seY“
.mih derussa elidocorc ehT
.MA9 ta ekowa yevraH dna maS
.doow dna rehtael htiw denil ,llams saw bulc ehT
”.erofeb slaem ydaer edam
eht ta od ot denetaerht d’eh ekil sreniart dna skcos ,partskcoj sih tsuj ni
.wodniw eht ot tsesolc dne eht ot dnuora gnippets ,derettum yevraH
”.ytrap adnik yknik
ykculnu er’ew fi
sgnirettum eldi ot dedaf dah klat eht
…wonk’y ,t’nseod revoR …lleW“
,naJ ot flesmih ecudortni ot htrof deklaw eihctiR
.os enod evah ot ton dedneterp lerriuqs ehT
,elbat nedoow egral eht ta gnirats nem htob
.derettum yevraH
.htob rof nav eht ni moor hguone evah t’ndid yeht ,haeY“
.aedi eht revo dellum lerriuqs ehT ”.renwo tnellecxe
.dekrims nooccar ehT
fo tnuoma egral a
,ekat elbuod a koot revoR
.deksa elidocorc ehT
…a ti ekam d’ew thguoht ew oS“
,kcaJ saw ydaerla ereht taS
.pu dekrep lerriuqs ehT ”!hooO“
,egnahc ot tops a htiw gnola
.tnelis gnillaf gnirettahc ylbbub s’eihctiR dna kcaJ
er’uoy ,naem I …I lleW“
,hteet sih tsuj htiw eno llup dna yrt
.nellaf dah thgin dna
”.eid ot gniog er’eW“
”?dne hcae ta tis ew gnikniht uoY“
.esuoh eht ta kcab denevnocer yevraH dna maS
…d’ew siht tuohtiW
,dnuos eht yb detpurretni saw noissucsid rehtruF
.rehpargotohp dna retiusruf
,mih erofeb ylgnisopmi doots
.ralimis gnihtemos ro ,kaO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.kcaJ htiw tog eihctiR yhw
– ”.revoR dna alegnA ksa thgim
.htaenrednu no dah eh gnoht kcalb ynihs eht laever ot sehtolc sih gniddehs ylksirb neht
.dias lerriuqs ehT
”?wonk’y ,niaga em ot kaeps emoc ot kooh eht ffo enohp ruo gnignir neeb yltcaxe t’nevah sklof yM
”.seiklat eiklaw elpuoc a rO“
,teiuq deniamer dah ohw tnecniV ta kool ot denrut dna deddon maS .dekrims yeht
.decsinimer flow ehT ”.teews
.pu kcab gnidnats ,detressa maS
.edisni thguorb erew dna yawrood eht ta deraeppa elidocorc dna xof eht sa
euqse-rennuR edalB a reviled ot ydaer saw alegnA sA
- .esuoh llams rieht ni ecalp otni etagivan ot gniyrt yad eht tneps dah maS taht elbat gninid tsav a yb detnemgua neeb dah egairram rieht ecnis rehtegot samtsirhC dnoces s’yevraH dna maS
.sevolg rebbur emos dna partskcoj
.delbmum esuom ehT
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  lufraF lacsaP yb
”?citsalp gnillik-tenalp fo stiB
”!fooW“ ytraeh a evag eH
.denetfos egaugnal ydob s’xof ehT
aT“ detraeh-flah tahwemos a htiw hsid eht ot gnirutseg dna kcab gnippets ,yltnahpmuirt dias maS ”!doof s’tI“
,elihw a rof dedlof smra
.elbat eht morf egdab ”mehT/yehT“ a pu gnikcip ,dias nooccar ehT
- ”.allenomlas fo kcal a tsefinam nac I fi ees s’tel
,meht knaht ton rehtar d’I“ .deddon yevraH
”?wonk’y ,yrt tsael ta ton yhw
”.aedi eht s’taht ,sey ,yldaorB“ .deriuqne naJ
.ti no nettirw ”samtsirhC“ htiw gnihtyna diovA“
,elbat eht revo decalp neeb dah sexob azzip fo tnuoma egral a ,ruoh eht nihtiW
,taes elbat rieht detacolla neeb dah enoyrevE
,moor gnignahc eht ni strohs sih no dellup maS
”.saw ylimaf eht ni eno devol eht ohw suoivbo os eb t’ndluow ti os mih no ffo ti debbof
.ytnelpa selcsum htiw ruf etihw dna yerG .yug yklub a saw
”?ti rof pu eb thgim ohw enoyna wonk uoY“ .dias lerriuqs ehT
,gnortsdaeh ,citegrenE
.retnuoc eht no ti decalp dna nevo eht fo tuo hsid eht deggard dna sevolg nevo sih no dellup
”.revoR dna flesruoy rof noitseuq a evah I“
.sraey wef a rof rentrap myg ym saw eH“
.moor eht ni srehto eht morf skool deticxe htiw ylno tem saw hguoht
.elkcuhc gnitaefed-fles ,gniwonk a htiw deilper lerriuqs ehT ”.uoy teiuQ“
”?rof ni flesym nettog I evah tahw ,oS“
.yawrood eht ni gniraeppa dna llems eht gniwollof puorg eht
.elkcuhc a evag flow ehT
”?laem samtsirhC eht rof esu ot gniog ew era tahw …lleW“
hguoht ,ylpmi dluow noitcnuf s’ti tahw rof mlac dna teiuq rehtaR
”?noitartsnomed a meht evig
.snoitpo reh gniredisnoc yltnelis
.nwotnwod ruolrap sgnicreip dna oottat reeuq a denwo
.owt ro lwob yggod paehc a su gab nac I teB“
,ot tnaw d’uoy gnikniht uoy erA“
…hhu yna rof ereh ton m’I tub ,seY“
.denialpxe eihctiR
”?doof siht si ,sreffins ruoy esU“
.yug eht ot deklat yllautca reven
.dat a deruos enot ehT .delbmurg yevraH
,detpecca na gnimoceb saw syot xes dna raew ypmiks fo yteixna eht
.etoyoc eht deksa alegnA
.su nioj ot detnaw yeht fi sdneirf ruo ksa d’ew derugif maS dna em ,oS“
a eb ot gniog s’taht kniht I“ ”?yekruT“
”.gniht samtsirhC nwo ruo od dna rehtegot sdneirf ruo teg
.moor eht dellif ecnelis gnol A
.kcab syad wef a ni desserd neeb d’eh strohs xetal eht ni kcaJ edisgnola doots ,myg
”.on ,yltcaxe ton …hhu lleW“ – ”?uoy era
,saw tahT“ .deilper maS
.eerht gniniamer eht tuo krow ot tnecniV dna kcaJ ,eihctiR gnivael dna
”…tub rehtegot eb d’ew woh dna tuo mih ksa ot gniog saw I woh tuo krow ot gniyrt dna
.tsal ta deksa yevraH
,myg lacol s’maS morf sklof owt
,elbat eht fo ertnec eht ni tas yekrut lufsseccusnu s’maS
.dnabsuh sih ta pu kcab gnikool ,dias eH
”?lla ta gnihtyna gniod er’ew kniht t’nod I flesti yad samtsirhC tub
,hceeps ”…eveileb t’ndluow uoy sgniht nees ev’I“
”.esruoc fo ,oot mih detivni I sselnu toN“ ,dekrims maS
.ehportsatac yraniluc a fo ,llems dna
.dennirg corc ehT
,tnemtnioppasid fo nrob saw I tuB“ .detnurg maS
.sregnif sih gnimmurd
,netae saw doof eht retfa
.puorg eht fo tser eht sdrawot htrof gnippets erofeb
”.ti ni yppup etuc a sah yrots samtsirhC kramllaH doog yrevE“
.detsetorp lerriuqs ehT
.dias eH ”.uoy fo rehtie rof
.deilper esuom ehT
”.nib niagrab eht ni seno paehc emos dah yeht
”.yb deppots I yhw adnik s’taht ,yltsenoH
,taht rof stiucsib hguone dah I fI“
,s’esuom eht no trihs tenhsif a
.ereht gnitteg m’I“ .ylmlac deksa eh
”.dnuor‘ yaw eht no hcnul emos pu kcip ll’I tub
.doof god laer tae
,etoyoc deksam-rebbur eht tep ot tuo gnihcaer ,dennirg naJ
,nrut ni devirra luaP dna alegnA
”~ti evresed yeht kniht t’nod I
.spil s’lerriuqs sih no ssik a decalp dna
rehtar a ta gnikool ,deksa maS
,lwob yggod a fo tuo dnabsuh ym gnideef em htiw elbatrofmocnu leef ot gniog erew elpoep diarfa saw I“
,su evig ot detnaw yeht gniht ylno eht s’tI
”?eb thgim ti yknik
,mih htiw moor a ni neeB“ .deksa maS
yppah m’I“ .dennirg nooccar ehT
.rutiuqes-non elpmis a derettu dna revoR ta revo dekool alegnA
.deksa nooccar ehT
,tesroc xetal a ni nexiv llat a
”!seY“ .dennirg eihctiR
,ydob s’lerriuqs eht ot dedda ssenrah rehtael a htiW
.mih rof gniog tol a tog s’eh tuB
,meht neewteb ruof gnirahs alegnA dna naJ ,yevraH
– .ysuolaej htiw hctiwt yevraH edam taht tcaf a
,kcab tas dna sdrow sih revo delbmuts yltnelis eh tub ,tniopretnuoc ot ydaer demees dna deddon corc eht ,ylgniwonK ”…deirram
,sriahc htiw etelpmoc won saw elbat egral ehT
,thgir er’uoy ,tahw wonk uoY“
”?nalp eritne ym s’taht kniht t’nod uoY“
,dnabsuh nwo sih dna god a gnidulcni ,sedis lla yb detovtuO
”.gniod htrow si tihs rieht esol noitaicossA srenwoemoH eht fo namriahc eht ekam ll’taht gnihtynA
,efil tseb sih gnivil saw eH
”.ssenrah a sdeen siht ,emmef oot
,skcos kcoj deruoloc ylthgirb ,llat ,sreniart yfmoC .retniw ni nevE
”~yad yna rekcarc ym llup nac sduts elpuoc A“
,riahc a detnaw eh ekil tlef eh fi
,yevraH raen nwod kcaJ dna eihctiR
,esuops sih ot derapmoc sa pu decreip yllauqe ,elidocorc gib a
.detseggus tnecniV
”?uoy t’nera ,taht gniyas terger em ekam ot gniog er’uoy ,taerg hO“
,ereh ni emit fo tol a dneps I hguohtlA
”~emit dlo yag a eb d’ti kniht I
.elkcuhc a htiw ti revoc ot deirt neht ,depmuj flow ehT
ot gniog er’yeht kniht ay’D“ ”.ffuts dna
”!etuc s’eh ,wow hO“ .revoR
,revoR eb nac I fI“ .deddon eH
yas ot elba eb ot evah I ,si ti wonk I won tub ,elbissop saw wonk t’ndid I gnihtemos yletinifed …hhu si ytrap samtsirhC yknik A“ - ”.%001 ni m’I yas ot tub eciohc on evah I
d’taht gnihtemos tsuJ“
”?thgir ,taht kooc ot woh wonk od uoY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.riap eht revo gnikool dna loots eht no ylbatrofmocnu gnittis ,deplug yevraH
.rehto hcae ta derats riap ehT ”?ti si
,sruoh 3 yletamixorppa nI
…ton ylbaborp er’yeht tub ,dnuora eb rehtar hcum d’I ohw klof fo hcnub a wonk od I“
,denialpxe yevraH ”.ti tog
”?yekrut eht od ot gniog
,elihw a rof moor eht ni gnuh ecneliS
.denwad yad samtsirhC
…owt uoy dna flesym tsuj s’ti esiwrehto ,ksa ot gniog s’eh myg eht ta sdneirf wef a tog s’maS“
,rehto eht ta maS
”.pohs eht ni slaem ydaer dna atsap fo tuo nar yeht tluaf ym ton s’tI“
,kooc kooc ekiL“ .deksa maS
.sepat SHV dlo gnihctaw dna skcajpalf gnitae ,VT eht dnuora deldduh uoy dna em
.hsup a ta ecno ti gnikcehc ,dapeton a ni tsil a gnikam
.demrofrep saw gnivig-tfig dna
”.kniht I smra ,hhU“
.dehgual xof ehT ”?wonk’y
DI sih revo recnuob eht htiw kcehc llams A
.devirra dah enoyreve ecno ylno tub
.nooccar eht ot txen yltaen decalp yot yhtrig dna gnol
.flesti myg eht fo roolf eht otno dna srekcol eht fo tuo deklaw yeht sa riap eht tem ,naJ ,nooccar A
.ti nees d’uoy dias eihctiR ,haeY“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.nugeb dah sucric yadiloh ehT
,ecapsdaeh gnikaerb tsomla
.lerriuqs eht ta yrrebpsar a welb xof ehT
.ytiddo yfmoc tahwemos
”~gnihtemos uoy tog evd’I gnimoc erew uoy nwonk I dah …hhu ,hA“
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”samtsirhC gnikcuF yreV A“
”.ydaerla d’!mahW toG“ ”?pu s’tahW“ ”.kcuF“
.edisni saw eh dna
tneserp gnikool-cillahp a ot detniop esuom ehT
.od ot tuoba er’ew tahw fo erawa ydobyreve si ,yakO“  .delbmurg ehs
yeht os esuoh s’rehtorb sih ni tif t’ndid tI
.resolc ni denael dna dnuora dekool esuom ehT
.sriahc s’ti dna ti
.elttil erow xof ehT
.rednop ot ezag sih detreva dna deddon flow ehT .detseggus maS
.lacitcarp emos dna cillahp emos
,ycar emos ,enadnum emoS
”.tey rennid dah neve t’nevah eW“
ssertsim sih ta pu gnimaeb dna roolf detanimal eht ssorca tnemirrem htiw gnilwarc sttim rebbur hsulp ni desacne swap sih dna elims yppah gib a gnirab
,elbat eht dnuora tas tetco ehT  ”.ho...“
”…adnik haey …hhu hO“
.ylregae dekrab eH ”!fooW“
.strohs rebbur kcalb thgit emos ni dalc
”.syadiloh eht rof revo gnimoc ni detseretni yltcaxe t’nia
,mih ksa ot pu egaruoc eht tog I sa tsuJ“
,gnoht a ni gniraeppa
.gniht eht revo ti epard mih gnipleh lerriuqs eht
”?azzip emos ni redro I taht ruovaf ni llA“
”~os gniyas em dnim t’nod uoy fI“ .dennirg tnecniV
fo tser eht ,riap eht dniheb morf dias naJ
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,sduts ni ylevisnetxe derevoc rehtael nworb-ffo na ni sevolg htgnel-redluohs dna stoob hgih-eenk
.decnuonna ehS ”.srekcarc emos thguorb evah I“
. dias eH ”.ma I ereh ,ecneH
”.raewrednu sih ni nam a htiw tuo gnikrow em ekil d’yevraH fi onnuD“ .strohs gnol gnihctam emos dna yesrej llabteksab nrow a no gnillup ,dehgual eH
,sruof lla no htrof gnidnuob ylirrem ,dna
– ”.leef I woh mih gnillet ecnahc ot evah t’nod I os pu snrut eh erofeb tsuj evael ot dnet I
”?elbat eht s’woh ,niaga ay ees ot taerG !yesuom yeH“
”?ti ekat I ,kcab kcaJ niw ot gniyrt llitS“
”.ni m’I ,ti kcuF“ .denosaer naJ
.ylmlac dias yevraH
.erats nori na htiw
.sgab reh fo eno otni dehcaer dna taes reh morf esora alegnA ,ni secils wef A
”.lleh sa yknik ,yhcnuar
.’on‘ tnaem ylraelc yrev taht yaw a ni ,dias maS ”.seY“
”.ksa ot elpoep rehto owt fo kniht ylno nac I“
,decnuonna maS ”.raew ot sgnoht dna kooc ot s’yekrut tog ev’I ,esac taht ni ,thgirlA“
.snoitpo owt evah ew ,yllacitsilaer ,kniht I“
tih yllanif dah retniw fo dloc ehT
”?maS yadot ’nileef uoy yad tahW“
.riap eht ta pu dennirg dna
”.gninosiop doof tcepxe ot gniog er’yeht kniht I“ ”?yekrut a tcepxe
,def-llew gnimoceb erew elpoeP
”?llew uoy ,yevraH olleH“
”?thgir ,tnemtraped erif eht rof 999 s’tI“
”.kcaJ rof riap a dna hcae uoy rof eno evah I
,sgnicreip fo rebmun elbatnuocnu na dna soottat gniwolf htiw revo lla derevoc ,ydob s’eihctiR
flesruoy morf draeh ev’I tahw morf tub ,niatrec rof yas t’naC .ylekil tsom ,haeY“ .deksa tnecniV ”?gniog era kcaJ dna eihctiR oS“
”.gnimoc era pup eht dna xirtanimod eht taht ecnuonna ot
– .yllufyalp delkcac xof ehT
dehsulb ,deplug tnecniV
- ”.owt ro oggod a tep nac I kniht I ,hO“
”.tfihs liater a gnikrow rof teg uoy tahw s’tahT .puY“ ”?sruoh 5 ,tahw
.nirg duorp a evag alegnA
.dehsulb esuom ehT ”.yasrep-p hhu ,ygro
.segap yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF sih no dnuof eb nac hguoht
.redluohs s’kcaJ no mra na gnitser ,dekrims alegnA
.edis eht ta llaw eht otni deggulp
kcaJ ot repsihw eihctiR raehrevo ot deganam maS ,nwod tes gnieb erew sgab sA
”?evah ti dluow yhW“
.triks llams a dna tius ydob tenhsif a ni naJ dna
”.klof fo dnik rennid samtsirhC lanoitidart
I ecnis ,dlo sraey nezod wef a er’yehT“
,snoitaroced yub og ll’I“
ot decalp tseb ton spahrep …gnieb revoR
,enilfoor eht morf ylgnivol depard sgalf edirp detrossa htiw
.delkcuhc lerriuqs ehT
.”~tuoba gniklat erew uoy tnecniV duts taht s’taht os ,hO“
.wap sih devaw dna detrons lerriuqs ehT
.gninrom taht bulc knik eht sdrawot nwod klaw gnol eht edam esuom ehT
.elihw a ni kcaJ ot nekops t’nevaH .os kniht I haeY“
,lufyalp ,yknuh ,suoegroG
gnihtyna diova ot tsedenmad ruo gniod er’eW“
.spih sih no swap sih tup xof ehT
.yldneirf demees yeht hguoht
,pu dnats ot devom dna don raelc a evag etoyoc ehT .yad sa raelc
.alegnA edisgnola llat doots eh sa nekorb noisulli eht ,teef owt no
”.rehto hcae ot kaeps nac ew os senohpagem emos su teg ll’I ,haeY“
”?kniht ay’d tahW“ .revo ti gnillum
.eihctiR ro flesmih morf gnihtyna nevig neeb t’ndah tnecniV taht deciton dah kcaJ
.flow eht ot rehto eht dna elidocorc eht ot rekcarc a fo dne eht gnidnah
,pal s’eihctiR no delgguns dah kcaJ dna
,ylivaeh detnit saw ssalg ehT
.resolc gnippets ,deksa alegnA ”?ti si
.nalp eht revo gniog ,hcae eeffoc a htiw elbat eht ta tas riap ehT
.desumeb ylrettu na evag neht dna hsid eht ot ffins enodrevo na evag eH
,kcaJ ta pu gnikool ,detseggus eihctiR
”?pu s’tahw ,thgirlA“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
”.melborp taht evah t’nod su fo emoS“
.guh egral a otni esuom eht gnillup dna taes sih morf pu gnibmilc ,deirc xof ehT ”!yevraH yeH“
.dne wodniw eht ta maS raen nwod naJ dna tnecniV dna
,sdik erew yeht ecnis yevraH nwonk dah eihctiR
,yrekcorc repap dna citsalP“ denialpxe maS
.dennirg lerriuqs ehT
,tnecniV deman ,flow ehT
.etisoppo tas flow a
.srieht nioj ot eugnot s’xof eht ediug ot daeh rieht gnitfil
– .deedni teef dloc yrev mih evag
.os erom ylthgils ylno flow eht
.gab eht morf sregrub eht fo eno gnillup delbmum lerriuqs ehT ”.htob
eno siht piks nac uoy
,ytisrevinu ot emac ti emit eht yb detarapes
,yad gnixoB no nwo ruo fo rehtegot teg ylimaf a gnivah er’eW“
.elbat eht no sdnah sih gnippat
?ti t’nia ,raey siht uoy dna em eb ot gniog tsuj s’tI“
...“ ”.sruoy ton s’tahT“
”?xof eht tem uoy evaH“ .dehgis flow ehT
.nihtiw sterces eht gnidih
.ni meht gniees rebmemer reve dluoc esuom eht taht gnihtolc fo tnuoma tsom eht ni desserd htob ,sgab rieht nwod decalp dna hcae guh a yevraH evag yehT
.skcals dna trihs denori s’esuom eht tsniaga yfmoc dna mraw delgguns
”samtsirhC gnikcuF yreV A“   yojne esaelP
.flow eht ta desaet naJ
.hcnul samtsirhC rof evirra dluow xirtanimod a dna pup a
.deifiralc esuom ehT ”.ytivitca
.nevo eht htiw elbmuf lerriuqs eht dehctaw eh sa spahc rehtael fo riap a no gnillup ,deksa yevraH
dna eihctiR htiw tog kcaJ yhw ees yllatot I“ .dehgis flow ehT
.retniw fo elddim eht ni gninrom ylrae na gnieb ti fo tcudorp a saw ti spahrep
,htolcelbat eht gnidlofnu dna nwod gab eht gnicalp
.evres ot gnitpmetta saw lerriuqs eht taht hsid eht fo ffo seye sih ekat ot elbanu ,deilper elidocorc ehT ”.ekatsim eikooR“
tnecniV ,elihw srekcarc eht fo eno morf oduL fo emag ynit eht yalp ot gnitpmetta erew alegnA dna naJ
.elpoep erom ro nezod flah a taes ot hguone giB
.ylmrif dekrab maS ”!oN“
yekrut denrub fo llems eht ,sexob azzip
t’nerew ew dias uoy thguoht I“
,dias ehS ”.taolfkliM“
.moor eht hguorht detaidar htmraw fo esnes a
”?gnineve siht neppah ot tuoba s’tahw htiw elbatrofmoc ydobyrevE
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
-- ”.emoc ll’I ,thgirlA“
”.sriahc eht ees uoy litnu tiaw tsuJ“
.staoc egral ni desserd
,yekrut a ylno s’ti ,xaleR“
,stsitra oottat owt
”?luaP ,ekil uoy dluow tahW“ ”.ni su tnuoC“
”.ti fo tsom eht gnikam m’I os ,gnitteg m’I ecnatirehni ylno eht s’tI“
”?wonk’y ,sdneirf evah tsael ta dluoc ew ,ereh ylimaf evah ot gniog ton er’ew fi ,naem I“
,maS htiw rekcarc a dednah yltpmorp saw enoyrevE
gnol a saw erehT
.pu tnew sdnah neveS
”.nuf ekil sdnuoS“ .dennirg yehT
.nosaes samtsirhC .rebmeceD
”?tnaw uoy od dne hcihw ,oS“
”?gniht adnik taht ,sodlid ta elggig ,rennid evah ,raew hsitef ni pu sserd ,ekil s’ti oS“
.elbat siht rof ylimaf ym knaht ot deen ew yas rehtar d’I ,yletanutrofnU“
gnola thguorb dah xof eht taht gab eht ot ssorca dekool esuom ehT
”.retaw emos dna smaerc dratsuc emos tog I ,ekiL
,eihctiR erew stiftuo rieht ni raeppa ot sklof owt tsal ehT
,elihw a rof ria eht ni gnuh sdrow esohT
.kcab sraey wef a niaga rehto hcae otni depmub yeht hguoht
,gnivil evissergga dna hguor ,naem ,nael fo skramllah eht lla erob erugif rednels siH
”.emit htneves-ytnevele eht rof rekarnooM gnihctaw dnuora tas eb
.deunitnoc esuom ehT
”.talf steunim 02 ni hsael a no ecalp siht ni enoyreve evah d’I kniht I
,gnidnats dna hcneb eht otno pu kcab rab eht gnisae ,dehgis eh
,lluf oot tib a saw enoyrevE
,ekil ev’I …hhU“ ”?wonk’y
.teerts hgih eht ffo
.suoires yllautca
”?esle enoynA“ .detseggus maS
,dedecnoc xof ehT ”.eseht llup tsuj
.derehtag neeb dah stnapicitrap thgie lla ,tsal ta dna
.ylmrif tub ylraelc ,deksa ehS
.rewsna mih tel t’ndid tub
,mih derussa lerriuqs ehT ”.siht od nac I
,edisni eht dnuora dna esuoh eht fo tnorf eht ssorca nwerts neeb dah gnitnub ”syadiloH yppaH“
htrof denael esuom ehT
,rehto hcae deteerg ylsuovren kcaJ dna tnecniV elihw
,niaga dna won ,hcaE
hguoht ,detaeper yevraH ”.dooF“
,dne eno ta yevraH
,og sesamtsirhC sA“
.lerriuqs sih ediseb doots dna
,eceip eht gnidnuorrus ,meht fo thgie
”.em naht uoy no erom tol a …hhu s’erehT“
”~truh t’ndluow ypmiks gnihtemos ni pu desserd lla uoy ees ot …hhu hguohT“
”~ygro evitsef a ,hoO“
- ”.nokcer yeht tahw ees ,ksa na meht eviG
”.pu-hcnup a eb ll’ti
.dnah eno ni dehctulc enohp
”yekruT ekil llems t’nseod tahT“
,yad eht fo dne eht yB - .deksa maS
,tnecniV gniyps ,moor gnivil eht ot denruter owt eht