goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tnuh reed tsrif ruoy si siht tub
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
si yrots s’yadoT dna
deit saw ruf fo tfut a dna
.edirp fo esnes emas taht leef ot nageb ilevuK
,tlef eh woh etatsrevo ton dluoc eH
.revil war s’reed eht mih dereffo rehtorb gib sih sa
,ria yllihc eht ni gnilooc ssacrac sti
.yaw nevig yllanif dah stoor esohw eert kao ylredle
,delbmurg eH ”.worromot ti od ew t’naC“
guh yllems ,thgit a otni xof elttil eht gnillup
”tseR devreseD-lleW A“
”.ssel on reed der a dna
,trons ylgu na tuo tel ilevuK
”.nwo ruoy hsinelper ot htgnerts s’reed eht ekaT .ti yojne
.deneppah gnihtyna fi
.ezeerb eht ni yltneg gnippalf
,mraw llits saw ssacrac s’reed ehT
.kcans sih gnihsinif
”.detsaw tib elgnis eno toN“
,thgiarts pu-tas dna deffuh ohw
ruf fo deb dnuof-wen eht morf daeh sih desiar ylizal ilevuK
.ecaf nrets yldetraeh-flah a no gnittup
”?efil sti gnikat rof reed siht ewo ew od tahw tub
.thgir saw rehtorb gib tub
.tsaf os gninrael saw rehtorb elttil sih gniwonk
,tnuh tibbar a t’nsi sihT“
.elzzum sih no deretsalp elims gums a
,edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc arakaS
,hA“ .nruter ni regnif ynob a desiar ohw
,ssarg eht revo dekar saw pitraeps enots dekaos-doolb ehT   xoFarakaS yb
”.emit eht lla reppus ruo rof stibbar tnuh I ?thgiM“
.tsehc s’rehtorb gib sih tsniaga flesmih gnitnalp dna
.ruf sti hguorht sregnif sih gninnur dna
,sehcnuah sih morf esor yob-xof ehT
.yltneitapmi smra sih gnidlof ,dekrims arakaS
xof elttil eht sa gib sa tsomla sreltna ynroht sti
ylesraoh gnilkcuhc
,kcen sti gnola wap a nar eH
.gnils a htiw slerriuqs ta stohs top ekat dluoc ohw yob elttil a tsuj naht erom saw eh evorp ot ecnahc sih
saw sihT .revo ti gnikool
”.dab sa knits t’ndluow reed tsohg a htiw gnivil tsael tA“
,ereh deppart eb dluow tirips s’reed eht ,ti tfel yeht fI
.elzzum sih otno tperc elims lufedirp yllauqe na dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.rehtorb gib sih tsniaga rethgit flesmih gnisserp dna seye sih gnisolc
sretnuh sselerac emos taht ksuh a ot dnuob luos sti
htgnel a htiw redluohs sih revo denetsaf saw tI
.taes a ekat ot rehtorb elttil sih gnitivni dna mih ot txen dnuorg eht gnittap ,detsisni eH
,ylleb s’reed eht ni edam d’eh tils eht ot derutseg xof gib ehT
edirp taht tlef eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
eldduc ot mih gnitivni
,hgual suocuar a tuo-tel arakaS
.nihc sih morf gnilgnad dna ffo-
.htmraw dna ytefas fo esnes a htiw mih dellif taht dnuos A
.decarbme saw eh tnemom hcae htiw
.ria dloc eht ni gnimaets dna mraw llits ,revil eht otni erot xof elttil ehT
,llits yal ti yllufknahT
,enot detareggaxe na ni detsaob ilevuK
mih ot railimaf sa saw reed a fo ymotana eht
.swap owt nwo sih sa
”.senitsetni sti em hctef dna ereht edisni lwarc ot evah uoy litnu tiaw uoy tsuJ“
,kciht llits ksum eht
.kcen sti no niats nosmirc gniworg a dna
.spil sih morf gnippird loord fo dnarts a
,gnilbbow sgel sih
,llik reporp tsrif sih fo
,sremmus net fo yob-xof a saw ilevuK
,ssecorp eht detaeper dna revo ti deppilf swap yerg tfed s’ilevuK .nosmirc peed a ti gniniats
pmuht-pmuht cimhtyhr eht pu-
,deredro rehtorb gib siH
,rehtorb elttil sih debbarg eh ,mra rehto eht htiW
.gnittilps morf sedis sih pots ot ylleb sih dnuora mra eno gnipparw
flesmih rof erac dluoc eh taht gniwonK
dekcip srae evitisnes siH
”.nik sti yawa gniracs dna smaerd dab uoy gnivig tirips reed yrgna na tnaw uoy sselnU“
nepo ssacrac eht tils eh
.niap htiw gniraes selcsum sih
,elzzum sih debbur eH
edaf ot gnimees selcsum eros sih
,arakaS ,rehtorb gib siH
.xof elttil eht ta eson sih pu-denrut arakaS ”?haey hO“
,yaw sti dnif dluoc tirips s’reed eht erus gnikam dna yerp rieht fo stirips eht gnitcepser tuoba lla wenk eh ,denworf ilevuK
sgut erom wef a retfA
.llik rieht gnirehctub fo ssecorp eht nageb dna
,erutsiom htiw kciht saw ria eht
.elzzum sih ssorca dehcterts elims duorp a htiw dnuora gninrut dna
s’ilevuK no wap sih tup eH
.dnoces rehtona tiaw t’ndluoc eh
.fo esu doog ekam ot derehtob ton dah
.reed eht morf ti dehcnerw dna
,trid eht otni raeps eht fo ttub eht detnalp eH
.ylleb taf s’reed eht edisni efink eht dehcaer dna
,elttirb a ekil paeh derruf a otni gnilpmurc
.kcen sih dnuora derettalc hcihw
.ssacrac s’reed eht ni ecaf sih deirub dna denway eH
.traeh s’rehtorb gib sih fo
hteet fo ecalkcen a rednu dekcut
.edirp fo lluf eciov sih
,dal elttil elbisnes a er’uoy wonk I“
”tseR devreseD-lleW A“:yojne esaelP
,hA“ .rehtegot sdaeherof rieht gnisserp dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
reed eht morf gnisir yliggorg
.egilbo ot yppah naht erom saw ilevuK dna
.doog etsat tsum ti
,ruf s’erah morf edam htolcniol a dna
.xof elttil eht sdrawot dna mra sih revo ti gnidaerps dna kaolc sih gnipparwnu
elzzum sih dellif
,mih ta nwod gnikool arakaS ees ot
.rof gnikool saw eh tahw dnuof arakaS
,gnigammur fo stnemom wef a retfA
”tseR devreseD-lleW A“ saw sihT
.nosmirc tnarbiv fo srettaps dna htrae denruhc htiw yhtlif ruf sih
.elbmur hcamots sih edam ti
,niaga delworg hcamots siH
,tsehc sih ni pu-gnillew
.enog saw revil eht erofeb sdnoces fo rettam a ylno ekil tlef tI
,nrut ot deirt eh sa delbmuts eH
.ruf reed dettam fo slufhtuom hguorht delbmum xof elttil ehT
,ylduol deplug neht
,reed der ythgim a yal mih erofeB
,mra thgir sih fo htgnel eht derevoc oottat eulb-daow A
,thguoht eh ,mraw llitS
.ezeerb gninrom yllihc eht fo tuo peek dna pu-
.mra sih ni ti gnilfits
,detroter ilevuK
.hguorht mih nur ot hguone prahs dna
,tnemevom naelc eno htiW
,klub s’reed eht nopu llaf flesmih tel ilevuK
eralg yrgnuh a htiw dehctaw ilevuK
”.rehtorb elttil retteb a rof deksa evah t’ndluoc I
,ylluferac revil eht koot eH
.setib dezis-dlihc ni
,detneler rehtorb elttil sih
,kciht sih hguorht gniwohs egac bir sih ,ynniks dna llat
.rehtorb gib sih ta sknuhc dewehc-flah gnittips
.yrtne fo tniop eht tcepsni ot esolc ni gninael
.sgnul gninrub sih gnitaoc wed gninrom eht
.nwo sih ti ekam ot
”.tnuh a erofeb ruf ruoy otni oop reed bur uoy nehw naht esrow on s’tI“
.srae sih ni gnihsur doolb raeh llits dluoc eh dna
.tleb sih morf efink reltna detniap a dehtaehsnu dna denrut arakaS
kcen s’reed eht gnittap ,delkcuhc arakaS
hcamots s’reed eht ot efink eht desserp eh sa
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.ruf fo taoc dehsawnu
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,xoFarakaS yb
.kcab sih no kaolc ruf taerg a htiw
,emag gib gnitnuh emit tsrif sih saw sihT
,xof elttil eht gnisaeler ,dehgis arakaS
,htaerb peed a koot eH
hself toh fo etsat teews ehT
.sekorts ksirb owt htiw loot eht gninaelc
,raeps sih no denrut xof elttil ehT
.redluohs sih revo thgit kaolc eht gnillup
,eert hcrib a delbmeser rehtorb gib siH
,slirtson sih gnillif doolb toh
rohtua noitcif-cirotsih diva na si ohw ,xoFarakaS yb
eerf nagro eht tuc eH
.redluohs s’xof elttil eht no wap a gnittup
,dluoc eh sa gnol sa rof ereh pu-lruc ot detnaw eH
.loot eht no thgiew ekil-rehtaef sih gnitser
,rehtorb gib sih sdrawot swaptoof sih deggard eh sa
sgniggel edihesroh dettif-llew fo riap a erow eH
,llik ruoy si sihT“
,tsiaw sih dnuora depparw saw triks krowhctap A
.desiar worbeye na
.redluohs sih no raeps eht gnitser
”.laiceps si emag gib tsrif ruoy
,hserf fo hcnets eht
,sevitomocol maets no gnikrow sdnekeew sih sdneps ohw
,revil fo lufhtuom a htiw dekoj ilevuK
.reed eht fo tnorf ni dehcuorc saw
”.rehctub ot llafthgin litnu su ekat annog s’reed ruo etar siht ta ,neht yfmoc teG“
etib tsrif eht ekat ot ,tnatropmi
,elcatsbo on saw siht tub ,ees ton dluoc eH
.ssacrac reed eht revo gnikool ,dehgis arakaS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.egnaro nrut sevael eht litnu peels dluoc I“
”?dub elttil ,thgirla gnileef uoY“
,edihwar yggahs fo
tsehc s’reed eht no wap a gnittup ,dehgis ilevuK
,deksa rehtorb gib siH
,desufnoc dna deracs
.spil sih revo doolb sreed gniraems
,redluohs s’yob eht no deggut dna redluohs s’ilevuK revo ti dekcut eH
,dekrims rehtorb gib siH
,demaeb xof redlo ehT
”.dub elttil ,rellik a fo sgnikam eht evah tsuj thgim uoY“
tsehc sih ni gnimmurht llits saw traeh siH