dekool hcihw rebmahc llams a otni yawrood a laever ot nepo gnigniws dna gnihcated ylwols
dehcaer eb dluoc erohs morf raf taob a ro tnenitnoc eht fo edis raf ehT
eveileb srotaerc 'senihcam eht taht si eno detpecca yllareneg eht tub ,sesehtopyh fo tol a s'erehT"
.dehcnual dna detcurtsnoc saw
noitcejorp eht ssorca dehsalf tcejbo egral A  ".dekcatta
tub edis eno ot segnih egral fo riap a erew ereht
,dedeeccus eW"  .snug yklub htiw
,ria-dim ni dednepsus gnignah ebolg a was eh elbat eno nO
.yldipar dna ecneuqes ni erif dluoc yeht hcihw
.epyt ydob sih rof dengised staes tuohtiw elcihev a ni elbatrofmoc flesmih ekam ot gniyrt sruoh owt txen eht tneps rotnevni nakhsrek ehT
no ti gnihctiws ,meht dlot eH  ".ecneserp
,ereht dednal dna ecaps eht deretne tfarc eht
,deyaws dna dekcor tfarc eht sa sevlesmeht niartser ot desu stsoh sih secived ddo eht no tif dluoc eh yaw on saw erehT
esolc erew taht sdlrow ynam revo dessap osla ev'ew tuB
,snakhsrek ylwol eht ot
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ecalptekram eht ta nwod seip tsaeb-kard fo elpuoc a htiw etarbelec retteb dah eh taht dediced eh
mih dnuora erusserp ria eht sa
edistuo ecaps ehT
.egaugnal evitan s'hsekirreF ni gnikaeps eciov lacinahcem talf a yb dewollof dnuos gnilbraw kciuq a edam rotisiV ehT
,tuo derugif ylbaborp uoy sa ,sihT"
.deilper redael rotisiV ehT  ".knarf
.drah gnipmup dna
,rehto eht ot nwot fo edis eno morf langis fo tros emos dnes ot sevaw eseht fo seslup esu dluoc eh
.ti dnuora gnittilf ,snwot llams sa egral sa demees meht fo emos
ydob reh fo trap a saw ti fi derednow eh
.meht desu reven uoy ,tuB"
.sevlesmeht ot taerht a tneserp
,dehsinimid secrof-g eht dna ffo
.srotisiV yb dednuorrus esuoh sih dnif ot
.deggurhs eneleS   "?neve taht od yeht dluow yhW  ?srats eht morf sretsnom gnillik-tenalp ni gnirb sevaw-gnol eht ,oS"  .deifirroh ,no dekool hsekirreF   ".spihs ynoloc eht fo eno tpecretni ot deganam neve yehT
kcohs htiw dezilaer hsekirreF taht erugif a otno sreyal ni
.metsys ralos eht fo skcor sselefil eht gnoma noitazilivic nwo ruo dliub ot deirt ew emit a rof dna
.teerts eht fo edis rehto eht ylerem erew ti fi sa
teef owt rieht ot
.daetsni tius eht teg uoy os meht fo lla egnahc ot roiretsop eht ni niap a fo gib oot s'tI
,eno laer a emoceb ot woh nrael ot hguone gnol egelloc ni yats t’ndid ohw nisnocsiW morf xof a si ohw
,srotsecna ym edam yeht os dna
.srae dna straphtuom reh neewteb tes
dne eno ta epahs-lleb a dah taht
".meht dednetxe ecneics lacidem erofeb neht kcab snoitareneg ruo fo derdnuh a tuobA
,esaerg htiw gnippird llits sdnah sih fo owt
retemirep eht dnuora welf ro depol senihcam yldnips riehT
ssamdnal taht htob morf
.edis eno no llaw devruc a htiw slwob egral ekil
snoitcerid lla morf
,htgnel ni retemillim a naht erom fo sevaw etareneg meht nees reven d'eh ,revewoH
,meht dniheb desolc rood eht
fo tros emos eb ot demees
.decnavda erom tsuj ,swohs nretnal ruoy fo eno ekil s'tI"
.deilpmoc rotnevni nakhsrek eht noitcepsni fo stnemom erom elpuoc a retfa dna no ti tup ot hsekirreF rof derutseg eH  ".daetsni
,stnev dna sepip fo sutarappa errazib a ni derevoc erew
dezilaer dna pu thgil sehctolps eht was eh detator ebolg eht sa
hsekirreF nwod dehcuot yeht erofeB
esuoh eht morf erutinruf dna skcank-kcink dellup dna
nottub a desserp ehS  ".rehtona
.wen dnarb dekool taht
dias erow eh enihcam eht dna
stiusydob deromra ni desserd erew ohw sdepib eht fo elpuoc a ta gnihsur sezis dna sepahs lla fo
,namssierK leoJ yb
ssam tsegral-dnoces eht no
,ebolg eht ssorca dnapxe ot noitalupop eht delbane noitacinummoc fo esae sihT"
.rotareneg evaw-regnol a
,edistuo yks yddur eht fo weiv a gnivig
dnuorg eht morf pu tohs thgil fo maeb a dna
"edis tnorf" eht htiw
pu dekool srotisiV eht fo eno raen emac eh sA
,yrenihcam htiw dellif
,kcab emac hsekirreF
"?ebircsorp uoy tahw rof evas ygolonhcet siht lla su gnivig fo daetsni
.knarf eb ll'I"   "?su pleh yhW
.uoy dnuora yna dnuof reven I yhw saw taht
eripme ruoy fo trap a eb ot tnaw ohw
.pils eht no nward sevaw ynam htiw
ytiroirepus 'srotisiV eht fo rednimer eht tub
".retteb neeb evah t'ndluoc gnimit ruo
dehcnual saw pihs ynoloc tsrif eht retfa sedaced owt naht erom yleraB"
,erehwyna pu tes eb dluoc yeht tub ,tey
,dehcaorppa yeht sa yawa llef sevlah owt eht dna
.erus rof meht ssaprus dluoc eh siht htiw
hsekirreF   "?pu meht dekcip reven uoy naem uoy od tahW"
sgniht-lwob eht fo elpuoc a ot txen gnidnats rof delttes hsekirreF tif dluoc eh woh rof ssol a tA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,snoitnevni sih tuohtiw
,eno siht ot esolc ytterp era sdlrow esoht fo emoS
.yb deklaw staoc etihw gnol gniraew dna
,gniliec eht otni tes wodniw ssalg a htiw ecaps nepo egral a saw tI
gnihtemos deltsihw
.denrodanu dna euqapo erew sllaw owt rehto eht elihw
.htgnel ni erom ro retemiced a fo sevaw etareneg ot elba eb dluohs eno siht tub
.ylsuoludercni dias nakhsrek ehT
,rosnes sih no ytivitca ni ekips a deton hsekirreF
,krad a ni devil ohw
.edisni no enog dah tahw fo tsom tuoba ycerces ot nrows erew yeht tub
,llaw etisoppo eht no rood eht dehcuot dna
,rotauqe eht dnuora gniylf thgil gniknilb llams a tfel dna
,straphtuom reh revo nwod dna seye reh neewteb gniog epirts etihw a htiw tub
,dlrow ruoy eulav uoy fI"
?taht od uoy did yhW"
neerg denrut thgil a
,llaw eht no lenap a ot revo mih del yeht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ecneserp ruoy ni sdnopser sihT"
stsop gninetsil rieht fo eno hcaer ot sevaw-gnol s'ytinamuh rof sedaced nekat evah tsum tI
delevel tekcor eht ,yllaniF
namssierK leoJ yb
"?sevaw esoht tceted nac uoY"
.eno tsegral dnoces eht dna
.wonk ot tnaw uoy fI"
,gnirats morf flesmih pleh t'ndluoc hsekirreF
stius rotisiV eht fo eno eb ot deraeppa ti gninimaxe no
,meht rof secruoser esoht tsevrah dna
thgirtuo su edavni ylpmis t'ndid uoy nosaer eht dnA"
?yawyna ereh gniod uoy era tahw oS"
efil tneipas rehto taht
oga sraey neves srats eht morf dednecsed dah taht sgnieb lacirtemmys yllaretalib ddo esoht ,srotisiV
.hguone t'nsaw ti tuB
dnapxe tcart yrotaripser sih ni sesunis eht leef ot nageb nakhsrek eht dna
hguone egral ylerab
.rebmahc eht otni deppets ehs sa
".diarfa tsuj er'yehT
srotisiV erom owt fo dia eht koot ti hguohT
elpoep otno dloh ot reisae s'tI"
,gniliec eht otni tes sthgil mid yb detanimulli rodirroc latem worran a nwod deklaw yehT
htolc fo parcs llams a dleh dna
.smra sih ni sparts eht otno gnidloh ylpmis dna
.flesti llaw eht ot dedlew eb ot demees ti
.egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
eripme ruo denioj elpoep ruoy fi taht kniht eW
hsekirreF  .erutcurtsarfni 'srotisiV eht tuohtiw
!dehtolcnu rotisiV a ees ot tuoba saw eh
.ecneitnes evlove ot seiceps yerp a rof suolucidir eb dluow ti taht gnirebmemer erofeb
,nehctik a saw demussa eh gnihtemos
,noitcurtsnoc rednu emod eno ees dluoc eH
noitadipert emos htiw
.secnatsid retaerg raf revo etacinummoc ylneddus dluoc ew "sevaw gnol" ruoy derevocsid yeht nehw"
sthgil erom yb denioj retal
.niaga taht yrt ton lliw uoy
.tius reh rednu dna woleb gniunitnoc
wenis dna elcsum nwod dial mra enihcam a srednilyc eht fo eno hcae nI
mih desaeler llaw eht nwod dehcuot yllautneve yeht nehW
.gnola devom mraws eht sa
tib elttil a hsekirreF derussaer tI
.deniamer krowdoow derettahs dna seriw dehsams tub gnihton litnu niaga dna niaga ti no nwod toof reh thguorb ehS
.gnol sretemiced 4.1 ot esolc saw tI  !sseccuS
.rotareneg evaw sih sa dezingocer hsekirreF
srotisiV neewteb noitacinummoc fo rennam emos erew sevaw eht taht niatrec saw eH
.gnol taht sevaw gnitareneg ton rof nosaer retsinis rehto emos evah uoy sseug I
lenap eht no nottub a desserp rotisiV eno litnU
.ti dekram eldeen ynit eht sa tuo gnideef llorcs repap eht dekcehc dna rosnes sih pu dekcip eH
.srotisiV eht fo eerht tif ot
sloot dna sehcuop fo tnemtrossa na rof stnemhcatta dah taht sgel reh evoba tsuj tleb a dna
.rotisiV a morf saw eh rehtruf eht
,rehto hcae ta secaf rieht detcerid eneleS dna rotisiV detaoc-eulb ehT   .desucca eH  ".gnol
laitnetop rieht esopxe ot tnaw t'ndid ylpmis yeht taht snoicipsus dah hsekirreF tub
.delaes dna depperp ylluf ti teg ot mih rof
detelped erew secruoser s'tenalp eht yllautneve litnu
ro ,rotisiV a saw
noitces depahs-elop gnol a yb detcennoc sgnir owt fo gnitsisnoc pihs egral a dehctaw eh sA  ".srats
,wodniw eht tuo decnalg
serugif detius eht no raeb ot stopsthgil sih gnirb ot daeh sih gnitator ,deppots eH
noitavreserp-fles fo esnes sih gnimlehwrevo yliraropmet noitangidni dna edirp siH   .deksa tI
.meht retfa gnisolc emod eht
,dnalni rehtruf swenis ekil-bew gnidnetxe tub
.esuoh eht tfel dna
,deksa eH  "?rof siht
,ereh emoc ot tnaw dluow yeht yhw enigami t'ndluoc eH
".psarg tnerruc ruo dnoyeb raf worg dna stenalp esoht ezinoloc dluoc ew
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
snamuharap fo bom a dewohs ti woN  ".delleber
,tsoptuo 'srotisiV eht ot ni dewolla neeb dah snakhsrek emos taht wenk eh
ti hcuot ot tuo dehcaer eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
neerg htiw degnir stils lacitrev worran fo riap a ot decuder erew tub
,drawrof deppets eneleS
.hcnebkrow eht no mih erofeb tuo deyalps
.sesnel ssalg krad fo riap a yb stopsthgil rieht
drawrof sgel eerht sih fo owt
,tnorf reh morf werg taht
dnuos gnissih a saw erehT
,sezis suoirav fo selcihev dna
redloc erew dna thgilnus ssel deviecer taht sdlrow morf emac yeht taht
stekcos ni detator taht serehps etihw no detnuom dna
.erehwemos dnal ot nageb yeht dna niaga pu dekcip srotor eht neht
.llaw tliub-flah a pu gnibmilc slirdnet dna seldnips cillatem fo retsulc ddo na
.slaid dna snottub lareves htiw lenap a gninepo ,deunitnoc ehS ".tniop
.elip sirbed eht fo edis rehto eht no dekrap
ekil tahwemos dednuos ti straphtuom reh morf
evael ot dah ew taht dediced ew yllautneve tuB"
.pu dniw ot gnitrats senibrut
,tros emos fo srotisiV erew demussa eh taht serugif emos dna yks eulb a htiw
niaga degnahc tI  ".metsys
,eviecrep ot elba eb dluow nakhsrek on taht
.rehtona ot tenalp eht fo edis eno morf segassem dneser dna eviecer dluoc taht
.nrut ni senihcam yldaed dna
,dedulcnoc eneleS  ".stenalp
.delleber ew yad eno litnu
bmot dezis-tenalp a otni dnaL gninrut retfA
seirots erom roF
.edis raf eht no erehwemos dednal ti litnu sthgil gnitibro eht fo seires a ffo decnuob dna
.sa egaugnal reh detalsnart ecived s'redael rotisiV ehT  ".niaga
.sevitan cirabrab eht ot sessenkaew
,yletelpmoc degnahc egami eht ylnedduS   ".snamuh-arap eht
,meht sdrawot deppets eH
.uoy tneser yeht fi naht
.ygolonhcet tnerruc ruo fo hcaer eht dnoyeb tub
”tsoL dlroW A“:yojne esaelP
.god.ecioveht ta
.did I ,sey" deilper hsekirreF
hsekirreF ot pu deklaw tius nat a ni rotisiV A
.mih ot kcab denrut eneleS neht dna
,wonk ot tnaw yllaer uoy fI
,dnaL si siht elihW"
,noitcerid sih ni sedis evacnoc rieht detcerid dna
tnemom a rof delttesnu saw
,syad fo elpuoc a ni netae t'ndah eh taht
stekcarb dna seriw reppoc eht ssorca splapidep sih deyalps hsekirreF
,aedi tsetal sih ot mrof evig ot
,toof gnol eno detfil
"?siht ekam uoy diD"
--- .trac maets a hctac ot nar eh sa
.srats eht gnoma tuo dlrowemoh nwo ruo dnif dna
selaT dnuoB yb snamuharaP fo edirP ehT
.meht rof yletal pu gnittes neeb dah srotisiV eht seriw gnol yssem esoht tuohtiw dnA
.gniliec eht otni tes snel a ta derutseg neht dna emit tsal eno slaes tius s'hsekirreF dekcehc eneleS
tuo loops repap eht gnihctaw dna
,ria eht ot tnetnoc negyxo rewol hcum a htiw
,snoitacilppa fo thguoht rotnevni nakhsrek eht yletaidemmI
?sevlesruoy ot taerht a eb yllaitnetop ew t'ndluoC
hsekirreF ytingidni siht yb degartuO
emit emas eht ta tub ,ereht neppah dluoc tahw tuoba suoixna dat a gnieb ot dettimda eH
.tniop gnitrats doog a eb thgim siht esoppus I"  .mih dekri
.stius esoht tuohtiw evivrus dluoc ew taht
.metsys ralos eht ni noitatibahni namuharap ro namuh fo ngis tsal yreve detalihinna taht senihcam gnitnuh deyolped yeht
tekcor a fo raor duol eht saw ereht neht dna
snoitats yaler detamotua yolped dna dliub ot woh tuo derugif yehT"
hsekirreF  .mih ta snug level ot denrut senihcam gniylf eht fo owt dna
yltneg tcapmi sih detserra taht gnihtemos htiw deddap saw ti yletanutroF
etihw deroloc egadneppa gnizilibats reh fo pit eht dna sdnah reh dna ydob reh fo
.uoy dnuora pu meht dekcip reven I
.ti was eh erehw ecaps ytpme tub gnihton saw ereht ekil ti hguorht dessap mra sih dna
,sevaw regnol eht tuoba wonk t'ndid uoy ebyam thguoht I"
.tnemtrapmoc niam eht ot no devom yeht erofeb ti enimaxe ot emit evah t'ndid eh tub
.no erauqs tenalp eht tih dna
.selop eht ta spac etihw htiw
demialc dah srotisiV ehT
,dias emos stius rieht rednu saw tahw ees ot dewolla neeb neve
seniltsaoc eht no desucof yarg fo sehctolps tops dluoc eh ylesolc erom dekool eh sA
.hsekirreF suoixna na yb dewollof hguorht deppets rotisiV ehT  .nepo gnuws dna
.yleruces mih dloh ot
neerg ni derevoc epacsdnal neila na fo tiartrop a dettops eh ecno
bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy
daeh dna ydob sih dnuora dedlom neht dna
,elcihev rotisiV eht ta ylsuovren dekool hsekirreF
moor a deyalpsid noitcejorp eht metsys ralos a fo daetsni
.seitic evissam erew yeht taht
,htworg dna seltsirb ekil-ssom
”tsoL dlroW A“ saw sihT
.dnuora gniyl strap eraps ro sexob loot eb dluoc taht sgniht fo yteirav a dna
ni evivrus ot tsuj gnihtolc laiceps dedeen eh taht dlrow dloc
ecafrus eht gnittops seitic yarg htiw
detniop fo tes elbuod a gnilaever
sevaw eseht hguorht segami ro seciov tsac ot elba eb ton thgim eh ,eruS
senihcam rotisiV llams fo tnemtrossa na saw retsulc eht taht ees dluoc eh
taht ssarb dna seriw delgnat fo ssam a gniyrrac saw ehS  .mih dehcaorppa
.srepsarg sih ni lairetam eht revo gniog
levon tubed sih tuo kcehc
,ragnah ro egarag
.rats nwo rieht dnuora skcor rellams dna
--- .drawrof toof eno
eht morf gnitaname ssel ro retemillim a fo sevaw trohs pu dekcip dah rosnes evaw reilrae siH
,ydob reh nwod yaw eht fo tser eht deunitnoc nrettap roloc ehT
.elcihev eht fo rood nepo eht hguorht tfel dna ,pu doots
,drow txen eht tuo tfel rotalsnart reh "...sa
ssam dnal tsegral eht morf pu tohs llaberif a ylneddus nehT  ".hguone
sezis dna sepahs detrossa fo selcihev erom erew ereht
retemaid ni htdaerb s'dnah a tuoba
.meht dellac dah eneleS sa "namuharap"
tius eht mih evag ohw rotisiV ehT
.emac yeht ,sseldrager tub metsys eht dehcaer yeht erofeb seirutnec neeb evah yam ti dna
elddim eht nwod tilps emod enO
htworg citoibmys fo mrof emos ro
,sepyt detrossa fo erutinruf htiw sevocla erew sedis eht ot
...sa nwonk srotsecna ym fo dlrowemoh eht
.detuohs hsekirreF  "!?yhW"
kraps feirb a saw erehT  .snoitnevni sih rewop ot desu eh rotareneg dica eht ot dael lanif eht detcennoc neht ,ecalp ni saw gnihtyreve taht dekcehc-elbuod ,seriw fo elpuoc tsal eht detcennoc hsekirreF   .sbmil-elbuod ddo rieht htiw sgnieb detius roirepus-os-ho esoht wohs dluow tahT
htiw dlrow a yb decalper erew dnal tessur dna saes llams eht dna
.egadneppa gnidurtorp eno htiw noitcejorp eht ffo gnittuhs
hsekirreF  .secnarebutorp ynob
llet nac ew sa raf oS"
secnarebutorp dnuor owt pu dloh ot
,kcab demooz weiv ehT  ".erehwesle
.noitacinummoc ezinoitulover dluow ti
.yleruces meht dleh trap llaw eht ot dehcatta sparts fo seires a neht
emoh sih no ni gnipoows senihcam gniylf eht eciton neve t'ndid eh taht laog sih no tnetni os saw eH
.erehwesle hcraes ot dah yeht dna
sdaeh rieht no shtworg llams ylno htiw
.mih desserdda dna deppots elfir a gniyrrac dna eulb krad ni desserd ,srotisiV regral eht fo enO   .delbbab eH  ".uoy
yllautnevE  .desaerced
.efil tneipas kcal yeht tub
sgnidliub depahs-emod lareves htiw derevoc ,dnalsi na saw ti
.tius nwo reh fo sparts eht odnu ot detrats mih ot txen gnidnats rotisiV eht dna deppots gnissih eht
resolc emac yeht sA
sesnel kcalb eht htaenrednu deedni erew stopsthgil reh
nottub eno desserped eneleS  ".tenalp ruoy si
,kcalb dna etihw fo sehctap ni deroloc tius a gniraew rotisiV eno ,yllautnevE
.ria ruo sah esab eht fo tser ehT"
.daehklub eht tsniaga kcab nworht saw hsekirreF dna
.noitnetta fo dnik gnorw eht gnitcartta tuoba denrecnoc erew yeht fi
.tius reh fo tser eht devomer ehs sa
si yrots s’yadot dna
,ecafrus s'tenalp eht fo retrauq a pu dewollaws taht noisolpxe evissam a saw erehT
dloffacs elibom a gnimrof dna lairetam gnitisoped ylwols
secruos evaw-gnol no ni emoh ot dengised senihcam erew yeht
ni derevoc tub nwo sih ekil htooms ton saw edih reh taht deciton eh nehT
,stleb rieht denetsafnu srotisiV eht dna
,noitaroloc ni kcalb yltsom saw ehS
,dednapxe seitic eht dehctaw eh sa dna ylwols laid a denrut ehs ,nehT
s'tahW"  .snakhsrek rof tliub
.ti no nwod depmots dna
.gnola ti gnihsup sllaberif thgirB
llaw eht morf detlemnu rood eht dna
sdepib denniks htooms elihw sllaw eht tsniaga denael srednilyc ssalg egral
.gnicaf eb ot demees erutinruf eht fo tsom taht lenap kcalb gnol a yb detanimod llaw eno dna
ecneics roirepus raf rieht fo emos hcaet ot nugeb dna
,seriw eht htiw dluoc yeht ekil
sdaeh gnidurtorp rieht morf derevoc erew srotisiV eht lareneg ni tub esruoc fo snoitairav erew erehT
,elcihev rieht ot devom srotisiV eht sa esnopser ylno sih saW  ".ti detceted eW"
dehsinav saes eht
.suoivbo yletaidemmi esle gnihton tub
gel eno ni gnileef fo ssol a yb dednimer ylneddus saw
sevals sa su desu yehT"
.sirbed detrossa eht denimaxe serugif detius elihw
,tsrif eceipdaeh eht devomer eneleS
,tniop denimretederp emos dehcaer yeht litnu edutitla gniniag ylidaets ,ylwols esor yeht tsrif tA
yarg nehsa tub gnihton gnivael yawa denrub neerg eht dna
,ekops ehs nehw yllatnoziroh denepo dna sdrawrof dedurtorp straphtuom owt eht elihw
.dekcatta neeb dah dnaL taht gnitats egassem a deviecer yeht
muh tniaf a dna dael taht detcennoc eh sa
.rosnes evaw sih dnuof eh litnu elip eht hguorht detoor dna nwod tneb
.hsekirreF deilper ",ees I"
stellub elpitlum htiw dedaol eb dluoc
taht dias eh sa noos sA   "?ti fo tahW
"no emoc ,llew" denotni rotalsnart reh
ylsuoiditsaf dekrow smra eerht siH
.niaga dnaL ot denruter noitcejorp ehT
,lenap rehtona ees dluoc eh
.denioj sgel reh erehw aera eht otno
dnaL ot hguone esolc erew taht stenalp fo sderdnuh dezinoloc dna smetsys rats ynam derolpxe ev'eW"
.niaga llaw eht otni gnigrem
,tuo denrut ti sA"
"?ereht saw ti wonk neve uoy did woH
.meht yortsed dna
rebmahc llams eht deretne meht fo owt eht retfA   .dewollof hsekirreF snoitavreser emos htiW
noitcafsitas rieht ot ni delaes saw eh nehW
desu erew sevaw regnol eht taht wenk eh dna
.srotisiV suoiretsym eht tuoba nrael ot ecnahc retteb a teg t'ndluow eh wenk eh
,elcihev eht ta derutseg ehS  ".su htiw emoc
,thgir derebmemer eh fi mutnegrA nalC fo eneleS ,redael rieht
.oga sraey ruo fo 003,2 tuoba..."  ."ee-ti-nam-uyh"
yllacitnarf gnitoohs dna
dednetni eb ot demees taht osrot reh fo trap reppu eht tuoba parts a erew tius eht htaenrednu erow ehs gnihtolc ylno ehT
.sroloc gnireffid fo htolc yvaeh eb ot deraeppa tahw ni segadneppa gnizilibats detfil dna
rebmahc eht fo edis raf eht nO
,trofmoc rieht rof stius eht ecneh
.dlrow sih ni evil ot tius laiceps nwo reh dedeen ohw dna
,llaw eht dna lenap eht neewteb deraeppa maes a ylneddus dna
,srepolretni eht sdrawot dehsad
thgil eht fo kcirt a tsuj saw ebolg yrosulli eht taht wonk ot
.rats etihw-wolley a gnitibro stenalp lareves fo eno tsuj eb ot "dnaL" gniwohs
,dnuorg eht no noitnevni eht dessot eneleS
.stenalp eritne meht gnivig er'uoy nehw yllaicepsE
.denialpxe eneleS  ".decnavda
bro nepahssim ylthgils ,nerrab a ot
tuo og ot stnavres etaerc dluoc yeht erehw tniop eht ot decnavda dah ygoloib fo egdelwonk rieht neht yb dnA
,htolc der fo tnemrag a tuo dleh dna
daeh eht fo tnorf eht ta selcarips yrotaripser erew demuserp eh tahW
llaw edis eht ni tes kooh a ot tius retuo reh gnuh eneleS
ecaps morf dnik sih yortsed tsuj dluoc yeht fi yllaicepse
stenalp sselefil eht no tuo thguos yeht secruoser eht dnuof yehT"
.kcalb tser eht tub
dnal nworb dna neerg fo sessam egral eerht gnitarapes saes evissam
,namssierK leoJ yb ”tsoL dlroW A“
,trap lwob eht no tser ot flah ni sgel rieht tneb dna llaw llams eht ni eloh a hguorht segadneppa gnizilibats rieht tif yehT
drawpu deleviws taht spalf ralugnairt erew srae ehT
snug 'srotisiV eht smraerif nakhsrek ekilnu taht snoitartsnomed morf wenk eh ,deppots
erutaerc egnarts eht ta sesnel gniyfilpma-thgil s'tius sih hguorht dekool nakhsrek ehT