.edisa sehtolcdeb eht sknay eh ,gnilbmuhT
.sgniw reh htaeneb tfil gnidnel-htmraw eht fo tsal eht
,nihtiw skool eh nehw ,lla retfa roF
retaw fo ssalg eht stes
,ti leef sa llew sa raeh nac eH
,ylretsewron gnitsug
.seirots erom on ,thgir llA
,mih ot pu ylkciuq spets ehS
.lleps a rof teiuq ni neht no ylf yehT .thgit yldaed
.smaercs dna thgil eht no spans eolhC
.uoy tuoba deirrow s'eH .krow morf hciR
selbbarcs nomed ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikaK m'I
,drawdniw ot staeb eh nehW
,thginot worromot ,nehT
,moor nwo reh ot kcab snrut
.llew sa taht teg I
wodahs esnet etitep fo mrof reh
.bmot a sa krad dna dloc sa si esuoh eht dna erofeb sruoh ffo dehctiws gnitaeh ehT .ereht s'eh
.eye s'noinapmoc sih hctac ot revo secnalg nhoJ
.spil reh nopu ezalg ytsurc s'ereht dna ,gnits seye reH
.sdnatsrednu nhoJ
yllaer t'nseod eH ?mmH
.lla ta egde on ,yrrow-kniht fo tol A .eltneg s'noitseuq ehT
.hguone tnemegdelwonkca sa ecnelis sih sekat ehs dna
llab a otni pu ydob gnirevihs sih slruc eH
.eciohc a ekam ot evah ll'uoy ,noos semitemoS
,edils ti stel tub spsag eolhC
.senap eht hsams ot hguone drah
.egdel wodniw eht rof spael ,dnuor snips
yojne esaelP .lardehna hsals
knis eht ot revo sedirts slwob dna etalp reh sbarg neht ,gniliaf sdrow
.lla ta knird taht flesmih deruop eh yhw erus neve ton s'eH
eugnot reh tuo stup ehs ,suoiruC
.yawa rouqil eht sehsup dna ti tuoba kniht ot spots eh neht tuB
.nhoJ ,etartnecnoC
.eye sih hctac ot snrut
.wonk ylno dluoc ehs fi ,hO
remmahkcaj taebffo na s'traeh siH
.ruomuh ta bats etarepsed a sekam dna
,ereh ni tuo gniyrc uoy draeH .yb esolc nwod
.yks gnineve eht otni
,retal setunim ytriht
.oot ,reh evol I tuB
.lliks reporp eht swohs dna
.edisa eciohc eht tup nac eh ,tnemom a tsuj
.edis s'potpal eht yb tsuj yksihw fo ssalg deretaw-llew eht rof gnihcaer
sevaw eht revo wol setam reh htiw gniylf s'ehS
.wenis dna niks dna enob fo sedalb tnetop ,worran dna gnoL
reyal yradnuob eht edir ot os tsuj sgniw gnixelf
,sliaf eh siht ni tub
,wonk ro etirw uoy rehtehw tuB
draobyek eht revo sehcnuh nhoJ
.htob evah t'nac yllaer uoy ,ti ees I
.hsibbur rrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrrR ...dna htaerb peed doog A
.nway eguh a selfits nhoJ
.yldrawni flesmih sesruc eh dna gnorw er'yeht swonk eh ,tuo era sdrow eht sa noos sA
.sraet otni gnivlossid snoissucsid denosaer ynam oS
.lla retfa dlrow ruoy si sihT
,ysae reven s'tI .nhoJ ,yrros m'I
s'erehT .ni seitrid eht sessot dna
.meht llac ot esoohc uoy tahw s'tI .seramthgiN
,meht neewteb ria tnelis eht ni noisnet eht ,eromyna krow t'nod sdrow eht nehw sdrawretfa dna sehctam gnituohs ynam oS
.aes eht setsat dna
,gnineve remmusdim enif siht
.niaga seirots ruoy gnitirw trats retteb d'uoy kniht I ,nhoJ
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sevaw gnilbmut eht fo yromem eht tsuj s'ti spahrep rO
sruobhgien eht tuoba erac ot flesmih gnirb t'nac eH
.won tnatsid dna tniaf si eciov ehT
.thgin tsal denohp drahciR .esle gnihtemos s'erehT .erom ecno ffo mih stuc ehs ,rewsna ot htaerb ward nac eh erofeb tub ,tsahga reh ta serats eH .wen s'taht ,ho ,ho ,hO .dah reven ew sdik eht
.kcab gnimoc t'nsaw eh tnerappa emaceb ti sa noos sa
.tey gniylf elttil a rof emit s'ereht ,no emoc
wohemos ydob elbissopmi ehT
.tnemom a rof snworf ehS
.emalfa seye ,elbat eht spals ehS
.ti tuoba kniht ll'uoy em esimorP
.lardehnA yb ecnenitsbA
.edistuo morf wodniw desolc eht ta yllacitnarf gnitaeb
.kcolc eht ta ylirrulb stniuqs dna seye sih sbur nhoJ
.thgin hcae peels ot flesreh gniyrc spots eolhC ,htnom a retfA
.taht wonk uoy ,ereh emit ym evol I
,mih sessik dna dnuora smra reh sgnilf ehS .ediw seye
.mra sih gnikahs si
.noitseuq taht htiw ti lian ot dneirf a tsurT
,reh ekaw ot ton sruovaedne eH
.yaw eht ni teg ton dna
.lardehnA yb ecnenitsbA
.ecaf s'naeco eht morf sehcni xis
.adnaromem laiciffo ni rohpatem dna noitaretilla rof ecalp on s'ereht tub ,emit nwo sih ni seod eh tahw erac t'nod I ,sey ,hO
.siht ekil reh ees ot raeb t'nac eh tub ,eromyna krow sih tuoba elttil yrev serac eH
yaw ehT .rehto eht ro eno siht rehtiE
.namuhni ylrettu dna cirotsiherp s'taht eciov a ni ssenkrad eht ot tuo skeirhs tI
.sruoh eht tnuoc t'nseod eh tub
.dnim reh ni gnilriws llits smaerd tsegnarts eht fo sliated-flah htiw
.laed ot yaw rehto emos dnif ll'eH
?won yas eh did esle tahW
.maelg wobniar a ni pu seilf yarps dna evaw a spilc dna
,sesuap ehs rood eht ta tub
.deb s'dnabsuh reh ni retsnom a s'ereht dna
.noos niaga uoy ees ll'I
eciov s'dneirf sih ,yllautnevE
.dlot lla naps ni teef ytnewt
.pitgniw ot pitgniW
elacs no dniw fo repsihw eht ,dnuos ylno ehT
.niks sih no reve sa thgirb sa s'nus eht hguoht
,ykriuq a si ezeerb ehT
,flesmih fo skniht eh nehW
,tsim eht otni mih htiw ylf ot sgniw sih sevird dna
.nwo ruo no selttab ruo lla thgif t'nac eW
.hcuot ylfeirb selcsum rieht
,emit erom eno reh ta secnalg tI
sih ni regnif elgnis a sgaw ehs dna spsag eH
.erutcip reggib eht gnissim er'uoy taht leef tub pleh t'nac I
efiw siH .sregnif htiw dnah a yltcnitsid s'taht ,seY ?efiw siH
.yadot laog sih si taeb gniw elgnis a tuohtiw skcats eht fo stiucric eerhT
.gnippird dna ysdus dnah
,dniwnwod snrut eh nehW
si yrots s'yadot dna
.yleritne gniht rehtona etiuq s'taht ,lleW .etfovA
.noziroh raf eht no sllauqs niar eht era
.ria-dim ni detlah laerec fo lufnoops
.flesti tneitap neeb sah
.lla ta esnes on yletulosba sekam taht esuaceb
.em yenoh erad uoy t'noD
.deirt ev'I swonk ssendooG .dneirf ym ,deirt ev'I .on ,shgis nhoJ
,noonretfa lla sthgilf level wol gnicitcarp neeb ev'yehT
,sgninekawa luof fo elacs a nO
,sseug dna mriuqs mih hctaw ot nuf s'tI
.hguonE .secniw eh dna
,gninethgirb ,neht dnA
,aes eht ssorca ecnad thgilnus fo stfahs dna swodahs duolC
,yad hcae krow retfa dna gninrom yreve
,yaw eht lla pu nworht si hsas eht tnemom rehtona nI
.emit ni gnis dna raor llits srae sih rof
.yreuq ot kniht t'nseod eh tub
.tsehc sih ni gnidnuop
.elbat eht no woble ,dnah eno htiw daeh reh sporp dna seye reh stuhs ,shgis eolhC
.seirots ruoy ssim I
.mih erofeb llaw dilos a s'tsim ehT
.yltfos srumrum dneirf sih
.thgin taht nhoJ saw ti taht
kcarc prahs a dna hsalps a
?flesruoy ot egamad suoires emos od yllaer uoy dna eromyna uoy rof gnikrow t'nsi enicidem eht nehw leef ot gniog ehs s'woh dnA
,tsew eht ni ylkciuq gnisir si tsim eht ylnO
.enod ti ees ll'ew ,shpargarap erom wef a tsuJ
,htaerb gib a sekat nhoJ
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,gnitirw eht pleh t'nseod tI
gnieb otni dekraps luos a htiw
,seiks yrev eht ot mih etam lliw yehT
.hsarht sgniw gnol
,htaerb sward erutaerc ehT
.erus rof neht dehsinif yrots eht teg ll'eH .stide lanif eht
.ti tpmetta lliw eh
.desufnoc dna yppohc era sevaw eht edit tsniaga dniw htiw dna
gnirolpmi sih fo lla serongi dneirf sih nehw ,retal setunim ytrihT
.kcats tsomtuo eht nopu dehcrep ,rotcurtsni sih nettogrof s'eh ,haey hO
,etirovaf sih sa nesohc s'nhoJ eno eht htiw dethgiled s'ehS
ereht si mih fo tser ehT
esruoc fo tub ,elbissopmi smees tI
.kcab doolf seiromem ehT
.aibrubus fo egarevA .rM ,tnavres livic ronim ehT .dnabsuh gnivol
sti sehctarcs ti dna
.sdog eht lla fo smlaer eht ot
,ekas reh rof dnA .taht dnatsrednU
tfil fo eugnot lasrevinu dna
.won thgir ton ,esoohc ot ydaer ton s'eH
,erawa semoceb dna tauqs-imes drawkwa
,tuo gnilbmut emoc sdrow ehT
.regnol setunim wef a tsuj esaelp ,on esaelP ?nhoJ
,shgis eH .ma2 s'tI
.shgiht ymmalc sih nopu mlab a si ria looc ehT
.etagnole elzzum dna lluks
,deb ylenol reh ni ekawa sknilb eolhC
.dloh a rof eporg swalc gnol
.tey mih dlot t'nsah ehs tub
.erofeb emit yreve sa nrettap daerd emas eht
,sdnah reh pu sgnilf ehS
,tib eno dnim t'nseod ehs dnA
.sserac raed s'revol a ekil mih sekorts ria eht
,dnatsrednu t'nseod nhoJ
derit syawla er'uoY
.ylper ni tnurg ffurg a snrae tahT
.rehto eht neht dna gniw eno tsrif
?kniht uoy od ,ot pu er'ew kniht yeht tsum revetahW
.meht gnidir deppots ev'uoy
,thgir lla ,thgir llA ?esaelP
.dniheb evael ot deen uoy taht efil elohw siht s'tI
.ni meht gnidloh neeb s'ehs gnol woh
,edis sih morf raf syarts ehs fi tespu steg llits nhoJ
.enola eciohc siht ecaf ot evah t'ndluohs uoY
.thgit-gnirpsniam dnuow
.elzzum ekil-tuons dna
sknilb dna sredduhs eH .evol ,nhoJ
.gnillappa dna nekopsnu ,detoor-peed
ecivres lortnoc ro esuohrewop sa sgniw eht evres ot
,elbat tsafkaerb eht ssorca reh ta sknilb eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,pag eht otni flesti sdlof
gnissim sa nhoJ detroper ehS
.enim ton ,sdrow siH .ecaf
?thgir ,taht wonk uoy ,nhoJ ,su gnillik s'tI
tneuqole eht ni yltnatsnoc mih ot kaeps yehT
dehtoot sti morf erats raluconib a htiw reh sexif tI .gnitnap
,ssenkrad eht ni gnidnuop traeh
?siht dnatsrednu ot noitanilcni yna wohs ehs seoD
,erutraped sih retfa syad owt
?krow morf hciR ?tahw ,tiaW
,mih no elttes llihc llams a sleef nhoJ
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.kcab gnillup dna
,tnemom a rof dna seye sih stuhs eH
.retteb swonk ehs tub
ydob ylniagnu na revo dna pu gnicra
.oga shtnom esoht lla
.revo detniap ylkciuq os eb nac gnihtyreve ton taht revocsid dluow ehs ,revewoh ,thginoT
.nobbir ot yltnatsni nrut steehS
,tsrif ta sdrow eht ssecorp
?won skeew owt ,tahw neeb s'tI
.eurt eb ot sdrow s'dneirf sih swonk ydaerla eh nwod peeD
,tcaf ni ,sgniw owt ,gniw yltsom serutcip eh
.uoy ot riaf yrev neeb t'nevah I
.dnuorg eht nopu esae ta etiuq reven s'taht
.moor deniur eht nopu ni stsug ria thgin lluF
.gnol erofeb mih dnuora lla selcric gniylf eb ll'ehS
nrut gnibmilc lufecarg a ni dnuor dna pu gnicra
.sduolc eht ni erehwemos pu llits daeh
,noitcelfer remlac nO
,stsaeb eht fo rehtona s'ereht ,sdog ho ,neht dnA
.yletilop sksa eh fi elihw a rof mih evres lliw sgniw siH
,niaga seye sih steem ehS
.sruoh llams eht otni thgir ,pat ,pat ,pat seirots yzzuf ,yllis
.pleh ot gnirad llits
?reh eveileb reve dluow ohw
.oot emit siht uoy draeh ylbaborp sruobhgien eht kniht I ,yllautcA .shgis dna
.lohocla yna naht evitcidda dna elbisualp erom rehtegotla ruomalc rieht
dlo emas eht si ees nac eh lla
,ecnenitsba sihT .denimreted
,reh tcerroc ot tfel htgnerts eht sah regnol on eH ?seramthgin ehT
,deksat sa thgilf eht hsilpmocca ot yad eht fo tsom mih sekat tI
,leef ot egdel wodniw eht revo sregnif reh nur ot sah ylno ehs neht tub
.edart riafnu ylssorg a mih ot smees tI
.pu evig ot deen uoy taht seirots eht s'ti kniht t'nod I tuB
,dekcap elcsum ,osrot dellerrab A
.snoorc nehT .sknilb nehT
.eugolonom gnimees a ,ekilmaerd
,deb otni dna sriats eht nwod kcab speerc nhoJ
elirbef htiw wena meht serujnoc dna
.mih hguorht hsarc aesuan fo sevaw eht sa gninaorg ,teehs dehcnerd-taews eht no revo sllor dna
.ecnamrofrep ruoy gnitceffa si gnitirw evitaerc ruoy syas
?retirw a gnieb ton
.stih eh erofeb ,won htaerb peeD
daeh s'dneirf siH
,gniriapsed ,tneloiv
,won nerdlihc ruoy era seirots esoht kniht I semitemos tub
won thgir pots ll'I
.tnemnrevog ot ecivda ruoy gnitcefni s'tI
,tlas aes eht tuo sknilb eH
ecnenitsbA saw sihT
mih ot gnillac meht draeh tsrif eh nehw sa thgin eht tsiser ot elbissopmi sa er'yehT
,mih ecaf ot snrut rehto ehT
,ikaK yb uoy rof daer ,llerdeH ennA yb
.sucof gnisol ,shgis nhoJ
.tsrif ta ton
.lamreht dna sulumuc fo hcuot tserem ta
.erom yna uoy ees yldrah I
.murts dna esnet snodnet sih
derit selcsum sih
luftcepser si eh taht ylno ksa yeht ,nruter nI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
,flesti thgilf fo noitanracni tcefrep emas ehT
,thgil eht fo sniamer elttil tahw ni dnarts eht no sezod eh ,sdrawretfA
.srae s'gnilgdelf a rof gnittif tsom selat cioreh gnorts
,egde sserttam eht no dehcrep
.ydob siht sevol eH
.sevac gnitsen gnitcepsorp er'yehT
.reh morf raf yrev ,rettam taht rof ro
.dniheb tuo liart sgel tnadnuder siH
.etal oot raf ydaerla ,esruoc fo
,selacs eht lla pu tpews d'ehs neht yB
rentrap sti htiw gnihcnual erofeb ,snoom ekil seye
spid pitgniw siH
.oot ,rehto eht ni dna dlrow siht ni evil uoy depleh seirots ruoY
?ees nac uoy taht ytivitisnes ynA
.gnol yrev rof ton ,era uoy sa tilps niamer nac eno oN
.ssalg dna emarf wodniw eht
.nwod rehtaef era sduolc dna tsrub swolliP
,thgin nmad yreve yduts taht ni pu er'uoY
.seye sih fo segde eht gnikac
,ylf ot mih ot tuo seirc ydob siH
,kcen denilmaerts gnol
.tsael ta elihw elttil a rof
slias yhself niwt ,yldrawkwa dlof yeht
.won thgir evael ot tnaw t'nod I .noos oot ,oN
.dne eht ni ton ,ecnereffid a ekam tonnac ti
,toof eno htiw esahcrup etarepsed a ,swalc tI
sruoh gnimoc eht taht noitacilppus tnegru htiw sdaelp dna
.peelsa dnuos si esruoc fo eolhC
,yromem nwo reh stsurt ylerab ehs nehw
.nhoJ ,thgir s'tahT .ereh denohp eH
.erac t'nod I ,yrruf ,yzzuF
,lla retfa rof oga skeew ruof fo sgnineppah egnarts eht tuoba luos a dlot t'nsah ehS
.syaw elbissop lla fo tseb eht ni gnihca dna
.nepo seye sih spans eH
.yawa gnillor ,srettum dna mih sesruc ehs rof
ssenthgirb fo scra yzarc eht ni dna eerf sraet pmal gniliec ehT
.wollof tonnac uoy ,evael I nehW
.sedisbus sisirc ehT
rotcurtsni s'nhoJ ,syawla sA
,dednuorg s'eh nehW
mih kcar taht skcohs eht sA
,laer rof s'eh taht sees dna
,si ti neht yb tuB
seye reh sbur ehs
.od nac I taht gniht elgnis a ton s'ereht dna
,mlap sih otni sllip llams owt sesserp ehs ,ereH
etam ecno sih fo ,ylmid
,gniw sih dekcilf ydaerla sah dneirf sih tuB
.erom ecno mih secaf dna daeh reh sgnah
.doow eht otni peed deppir seguog elpirt eht fo seniltuo eht
,deirt reve uoy evaH .dnik eb lliw
na otni flesmih sevaeh eh ,edisbus ylwols
resu hsals ten.ytiniffaruf ta dnuof eb nac
,lufhtiaf emas ehT .nhoJ
dexif ,sehtolcdeb deniur eht dennib
.thginot retpahc siht hsinif ot stnaw yllaer eh dna ,tib eno ton
,yltfos tub ,mih ot semoc
,krow erom deen slliks thgilf reh taht ylbaroda os sterf eH
frus gnilbmut eht morf mih gnirb
.lliw I .seirc nhoJ
,llew ,deirt reve uoy evah ,wonk uoy
,wena tuo seirc deb eht no erutaerc eht yltnatsnI
.rehto eht htiw hctal eht ta yllacitnarf sekar
.sllug eht fo selkcac gnikcom tnatsid eht dna niks dna
,seciohc syawla era erehT
.dneirf ym ,og ot uoy rof emit s'tI
,yltpurba sdnats ehS
.tey eno tsrow sih ylbaborP .siht ,eno dab A
.sllaw eht ffo morf ylf serutciP
.liat eht ,meht retfA
.deined eb tonnac taht llac a s'ti dna
sniatruc sti ,ediw selim evif tes egats a
.htaerb regnorts a gniward daetsni
won niatrec si ehS
.ygde dna deyarf ,neht hgis a dna htaerb peed A
,thgin eht fo elddim eht s'tI
?flesmih fo sevlah owt neewteb esoohc ylbissop eh nac woH
syad sah llits ehS
sdnuos ylpmis eh ,revewoh ,woN
,rellif eht ni tniap wen eht htaeneb tsuj
.sliat sih morf ylraelc erutaerc eht dezingocer ehs ,emac thgilyad eht ecno dna
?yeht t'nera ,esrow gnitteg er'yehT
.enod ti teg ton lliw gnimaerD
ylwols dnuor daeh reh senarc ehS .yadot
,emit emos rof mih ta gniwalc neeb tcaf ni sah eciohc elbissopmi sihT
,eno siht gnidulcni ,seirots sih fo tsoM
.pets drawrof a sa ti stnuoc ehS
,yllautnevE .sregnif gnilbmert
,niaga ecno nokceb sretcarahc siH
.truh reh ees ton lliw I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,gnihctah ydaerla s'eh seirots eht fo reh sllet eh sa
.gnihtyna rof ton ,won pu ti evig t'ndluow I
.seirots yrruf er'yehT ?tahW .yrruF
.smiws noisiv siH
.thgin eht otni kcab
.wols dna etarebiled
.mra sih gnikahs si enoemos dna thgin eht fo elddim eht s'tI ?nahtanoJ
.net dilos a ti evig d'eh
,seramthgin eht htiw gnipleh seirots eht tuoba tihsllub taht eveileb ot em tcepxe erad uoy t'nod dnA
,yltnesba ,srednow eH .etib dica na htiw dehcte hcae
rehtegot pu esir owt ehT
.mees yeht woh si sdrows gnivruc deriaP
uoy gnisol m'I ekil s'ti
.ereh noitpo hcum evah I ees yllaer t'noD
,tnaw uoy fi diputs m'I yaS
.kcatta fo elgna dna ecnelubrut fo gard dna