.”gnikcah“ rehtob t’nod I
sciluardyh lairtsudni fo ecrof eht htiw sehsup thguac s’eh redilg ragus elttil yllirf eht nehw
.ruf tew ym ni sdnal ti sa dnuos ”talps“ a gnikam
.ssalg denekrad ees I dna ygolocra eht fo edis eht pu seirots owT
.egarots lainarc otni sdnoces owt rednu ni setybatez owt tniop ruoF
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,lerdnaK yb
.tsil eht ot ti dda ll’I
.dehsurc ydob dna dekcarc esnel—aremac lanosrep sih ees dluoc I mrofinu laminim sih fo redluohs eht nO  .od dluoc I taht woN
?hgih ma I sa gnol sa liaT
,krowkcolc ekil tsuj ,htnom yreve dnA  .lacigol er’yehT  .ykcinif er’yehT
.pu hctac slortap lairea eht erofeb modeerf tnatsid sdrawot deeps fo tnuoma doog a teg nac I erugif I
,pu selim eerht morf dna
.lufhtuom elohw a ton ebyaM  .yakO
.ytirucesrebyc fo sdog eht ot pihsrow enaforp fo ynatil a si eno hcae nO  .seton ti tsop era
.uoy thguac evah dluohs yllaer I sthgir lla yB
:msiurt eno no tnuoc I
.srewot owt neewteb ni gnidilg m’I sa ffo ti erif I os ,elihw a ekat thgim yreuq txeN
.nepo reward eht hsup dna srelbmut eht ngila ot yalp s’pup s’tI
,mih ees neve t’nac I
.atad proc pot rof setar tekram kcalb htiw railimaf t’nsaw poc-a-tner ralucitrap siht taht lufknaht yltnelis m’I
.lahtel etiuq eb d’ti
yawa si yreuq txeN
.enecs eht morf tixe efas ym eetnaraug ll’taht sloot wef a dna
.mih rezat I neht dnA  ”.riaf s’tahT“
.llor dna sgniw ym kcut em stel sexelfer deriw ylno dna
,thguac yletinifed m’I elihw tuB
.gnidliub lautuM s’noyL eht sdrawot ht8 ssorca edilg I dna
.egnahcxe ot ydaer m’I syas rexif ym ot eton A
.kcurt wot gniwols a dniheb yliratnemom sraeppasid dna
.niaga em revo sehsaw ranos sa elgnit a leef I ,renroc txen eht nrut neve I erofeB
.sdnoces ni tuo dna ni m’I
.thguoht hcum ti evig ot evah t’ndid eH  ”.oN“   .ksa I
.deeps ta ciffart hguorht gnivaew
.sgniw lacigoloib no detnuom rekcarc-efasrebyc edarg-lairtsudni na ot sloot gniretne-dna-gnikaerb fo yteirav nworg-emoh eht morf meht gnivorpmi
.elkna ym otno gnidloh pitgniw dewalc eno
.aremac derarfni gnikcart noitom a
.mrala eht ffo gnittes tuohtiw meht seirf eslup citengamortcele trohs A
tserra na t’nsi sihT  .oedor tsrif ym t’nsi sihT  .ti teg I ,hO
.luah s’thgin sih ot derapmoc loop eht ni pord a yldraH
.moc.enilnoyxof.www no
dennamnU  .ria eht ni si sreppohc fo dnuos eht
.skcirb eht morf spird dna ecaf ym srettaps tI
?seye egral ylhsikaerF
.srellik niap fo noitcejni nA
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,htnom a eno ,sraey rof no tnew yeht
.drocer ym no doog yllaer kool dluow ralloc a gnikniht ma I ereh dnA
,gnizeerf si ria eht edutitla siht tA
”?neht ,on a s’taht sseug I os ,hO“
.sregnif ym hguorht thgiarts stoohs eh dna
”.ot evah t’nod uoY“
”!321drowssaPAsIsihT“
.ereht edih ot secalp hguone naht erom
.etsatretfa on dna ,rettib eht htaeneb teews tib A
.yvaeh tlef llits yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.liat ym rednu pu pit gnihctiwt sih sehsup eh sa wodniw eht tsniaga hctorc ym sdnirg eH
”.rebilac ruoy fo reciffo na rof wol oot raf s’tahT“
.dniw eht ni elggiw srae siH
.oot ”larutan“ neeb dah efil xes reh sseug I os
neht dna ,kcab ym tsniaga gnihctiwt s’eh neht dnA
?htrow lautca fo gnihtyna em nevig ehs daH
,stniop dna sevruc fo noitcelloc prahs A
.ssalg eht hguorht su gnihctaw s’enoemoS
,moor eht ssorca renroc eht nI
.sregnif ym tsniaga hctiwt srae gib siH
.tius noelemahc ym hguorht mraw
.llet t’nac I ruf ym ni muc sih fo hcum os s’erehT
,stif taht eno dnif ot etunim a em sekat tI
)llams neeb t’ndah ti dna(
mih dnuora hcnelc ot gniyrt m’I erehw neewteb gninnur llits diuqil fo sehsug ehT
.kaerb a deen I  .hcum oot s’tI
.em dnuora sgniw sih sah eh dna—ti dnA  .snikneJ ruhtrA
.uaerub noitartsiger eht otni thguob d’I roodkcab eht sselb I
.ekorts I sa gnidliub eht ot thgit no sdloh ruhtrA   .lla ta dab toN
.sredilg gnoma gnik a ekil evil I
s’ereht dna ,yawa skcolb eerht si gnidliub tekramyaH dlo ehT
,decitonnu eb ot tius noelemahc ym deen neve t’nod I
,edilg I  .em naht retsaF
.taht ekil eugnot a tog ev’uoy fi toN
.ti ot pu bmilc ot emit hcum oot ekat t’ndluow ti tub
.ylf ew erehw no yas orez tog ev’I ,sedis ym ot dezeeuqs spalf-gniw ym htiW
.sretpoc ytic woleb senal revoh woleb sliar mart woleb srac dnuorG
.ega ylrae na yb ymotana redilg ragus eht ni noitacude ym dah d’I
.edistuo ria dessecorper yrotcaf eht naht esrow dellems eloh yrots-dim elttil ruo os ,stnecs larutaN
,sffuc sih htiw sgelerof ym fo eno hctal ot deganam s’eH
.raed ,htiw uoy ees ot retteb eht llA
.noitcartsid a fo hguone tsuJ   ”?kcuf eht woH“
.emit yna ta em evah dluoc eh evorp ot tsuj fi sa ,em sefarts eH
.llet t’nac I tub ,gnimmuc m’I kniht I
.ydob ym yb denoihsuc si tcapmi s’tab eht ,esruoc fO
,won ti deen ll’I kniht I taht toN
.ylleb ym otno diulf taht fo erom gnilbbird dna sgel daerps ym neewteb gnihctiwT
.tra gnikcuf fo eceip a m’I
.erus m’I ,ffo wohs ot dna ,hO
.niaga desolc retsloh neddih ym bmuht I
.sderc 29031
.VT gnihctaw s’enoemoS
.seog eh sa raf sa s’taht
.ti fo dnoces a neve toN
.foor eht ot pu lwarc I sa em pots t’nseod eH
.lufetargnu m'I kniht t'noD
”?ecnad ew llahs ,oS
.meht morf gnisir maets eht leef dluoc I tub
.woleb flug gninway eht otni meht pord dna
.srae ym otni yldeggar gnihtaerb s’eH
,lwarps salegnA weN eht fo enilyks eht sa evila sa etiuq gnihtyna t’nsaw ereht dna ,evil ot tnaw I
.shgual eH  ”!etuc os s’ti ,wwA“
,sretsis owt ym dna em htiw neeb d’ehs nehw rotcod a ees ot enog d’ehs taht lufetarg eb dluohs I sseug I
.em ta flesmih sehcnual eH
”.tserra rednu era uoY  .tsiser t’noD“   .elohssA
nepo toohs seye siH
.shtaerb neewteb ni psag ot seganam eH  ”--I ,yrroS  .tihS“
.yenom fo tol a mih gnivig m’I taht kniht mih sekam tI
.em rof drocer a yletinifed s’taht ,setunim ynam sa tsuj ylbaborp ni semit eerhT
,llif yllautca ot namuh yna rof egral oot yaw ksed a dniheb riahc evitucexe yfmoc eciN
.em otni ylivaeh snael dna
.edilg ym sniur erutseg eht sa llafeerf a otni elbmut dna
.kcils dna tew s’eh dna
,yawa gnihsup m’I hguoht nevE  .doog yllaeR
.tsirw ym bmuht I  ”?gnikniht I saw tahW  !ton esruoc fO“   ”--t’nac I  -I“
.em edisni tfahs sih fo eslup hcae htiw ylleb sih tsniaga kcab em gnillup
.diap ydaerla ev’uoY
,em dniheb s’ruhtrA  .erac t’nod I
.ylf em hctaW  ?gel-ot-mra sbeW
.tsilarutan a neeb d’ehs ,os nevE
.eciffo evitucexE  .smrof pam A
,eb ot meht detcepxe I erehw tsuj ,eno pot eht nI
.tekramyaH eht rof flesym elgna I emit siht dna ,eromyna llits em peek ot gniyrt ton s’eH
.em sa llams sa gnihtemos tuo kcip t’nac radar riehT
.sevaew eh ,egdod I
.lla ta thguac eb ton ot si nalp eht ,daetsni oS
.esir-hgih dehsinif-flah a ot ciffart racrevoh fo reyal tsrif eht revo sretem ytnewt spalf dna edis eht ot em selkcat eH
.dnoces eht rof moor t’nsi yletinifed ereht neht ,yarps gnikaos tsrif eht rof moor t’nsaw ereht fI
,tsirw ym ta ecnalG
,niaga em no si ruhtrA
.rettam t’ndid taht tub
.ofni em evig ,yakO  .tihS
.yrots retteb a mih sevig ti ,yawynA
.eros leef ot gnitrats ydaerla m’I ,kcuF
niks ym htaeneb stnemgiP
pukcab rehto ym regnif dna nworf I
sgniw debbew dna
.nwod looc sgel ym ni sciluardyh eht tel ot niaga pots I
.daetsni mih hctac em tel ll’eh ,emit txen ebyaM
.snoitacifidom eht fo naf a neeb t’ndah moM
.reyolpme ym ot kcab em knil ot muinarc ym morf sliated hguone tfil llits dluoc kysp detnelat a ,nar I locotorp epiw-dnim a doog woh rettam oN
.trams eb ,ruhtrA ,no emoC
pirg dennuts sih fo tuo kcud I nehw revocer ot sdnoces wef a mih sekat tI
.emit siht stigid evif ylnO
”.4drowssaPweNAsIsihTsemaJyakO“
.dab os leef t’nseod tahT
.mgarhpaid ym otni teef sih sevird mutnemom nehw dehcnup neeb ev’I ekil sleef ti dna
.tnelis niamer ot thgir eht evah uoY
.em dniheb ni gninoops ruhtrA htiw tsrif-ecaf llaw gnidliub driht ym teem I dna ,em dnuorrus sgniW  .kcuF
ecafrus tnatsid eht revo miks sthgil elttil noillim A
.dooG  .gnihtaerb s’eH
,mih rof sgel ym daerps I
.depacse ylerab tsuj uoy ekil kool ti ekam ot evah ll’eW“
,ruf ym htiw ,taht noitalusni hguone sah tius noelemahc ym tub
.tius noelemahc ym gnola pu syarps dna sregnif ym fo tuo sehctiwt tI
.dewollof eh sa liat ym htaeneb tsuj tuons sih stup taht dnA
”!potS  !ruhtrA“  .tsrif knird a em yub mih ekam d’I ,em tserra ot gniyrt t’nerew eh fi ,kcuF
.noisiv sti tuo snrub
.debtalf eht fo kcab eht ot depparts rac strops eht htaeneb s’eh
,em tsap sehsoohw gnihtemoS
.yliratnemom ria eht ni slialf dna walc eno htiw pirg sih sesol eH  .orez a dda I
,pu kcab piz ot trats I
.ecaf sih ni hgual I  ”!haH“
.siht naelc-yrd ot deen ot gniog m’I ,naM
.elbasunu s'ti—lanoitidart s'ti fi erac t'nod I
emit siht evom t’nseod eH
.thgir dna tfel gnitsiwt
.orez rehtona dda I nehT
.kcul gnikcuf ym tsuJ
.siroirepus eadiruatep em llac yehT
,mih dnuora egde ot yrt I
!detnalpmi yllaicifitra eb nac sbmuht tuo snrut ti ,rednow fo rednow dna
.ssarg fo sedalb neewteb seilf-wolg ekiL
.detnim gnikcuf yleniuneg m’I
.pu thgil seye siH  .selims eH
.edam neeb d’yeht yaw eht naht rehtar
.sretupmoc etah elpoep ssenisub
.renroc eht no krowenots eht ot flesym hctal I nehw em no ni gnisolc s’eH
.nwo sih fo skcirt wef a sah etad ym smeeS  .nmaD
,ruoh rep selim ytfif ta tsap sehtycs rotavele sserpxe na thgir ym ot teef ytnewT
,dednecsa na fo nos eht saw I
.krow em ees dluohs uoY
,ti htiw em ekorts nac eh taht hguone gnol s’tI
.cirtcele si noitasnes ehT
.htaerb sih rednu smuh eH
.ssalg eht no gnibbew evitisnes ym hctac ot ton erus ekam I
.detapicitna evah reven dluoc I snoitacilppa sah gniht tahT
.wodniw s’rekoolno desufnoc eht nwod hsaw ot trats I  .ti pleh t’nac I
.ecirp eht fo retrauq a ta erots lacol eht morf sananab roirepus yllaciteneg dna seotamot tcefrep yub dluoc ew nehw sremraf cinagro morf selbategev derolocsid dna stiurf ynwarcs os ,doof larutaN
-“  .tfahs ym dnuora semit eerht slruc eugnot gnol sih sa ecnetnes-dim pots I
niaga sffuc eht rof gnilbmuf mih leef I
.reddur a dellac s’tI
.hctac ot senohporcim ytiruces eht rof hgih oot ,snoitarbiv cinosartlu stime wodniw eht no dnaH
.ylleb ym tsniaga gnimrif dna shgiht ym tsniaga gnisnet htgnel taht leef nac I sborht eh nehW
tsirw ym stih esnopseR
.thgis-thgin ym evreserp ot
.dab oot etsat t’nseod eH
.sehsif aes peed morf dereenigne esrever ecnecsenimul-ohpsohp htiw edih ym hguorht dewolg tI
.ekat ot gnilliw m’I ksir a s’ti tub ,ksir a s’tI
.meg a thguac yllaer I ,nam hO  .hgual I
.doog sleef taht ,kcuf ,hO
.siht ekat t’nac I ,kcuf hO
?dias I gnihtemos ti saW
,siht fo yna gniyas tuohtiW
.niaga tsirw ym rof hcaer ot moor hguone em sevig eH
,thguac erew I fI
.em fo tuo edils mih leef I
.teef derdnuh wef tsal eht rewop nwo ym rednu bmilc ll'I dna ffo setunim wef a ekaT  .syob ,boj dooG
.retal tnemom a em snioj eH
.thgin eht fo erom dah I hsiw I
.wodniw eht hguorht tuo kcaB
.tihspid ,on a ton s’ti esruoc fO
.yllaer ,gnihtyrevE  .sey ,lleW
.em sesserac ranos siH
.daeh sih revo dnah ym nur dna don I
.diap gnitteg m’I tahw fo retrauq a neve ton s’tI   .suovren tca I
s’eh nehT   .ylhguoroht tnemtaert eht gniyojne s’eh taht tseggus
,rewoT ailongaM fo elohw eht wohs
,lim flah a dna owt ym peek ot teg uoy od ylno toN  .ibila tcefrep A
.drowssap sih togrof OEC-
.yks eht etanimod ot detrats seigolocra etaroproc gnirewot eht ecnis reve
.ssergorp ym dekcart oottat trams a erehw ruf fo eerf yltnenamrep tpek niks-xuaf erab fo hctap a si ti nO
.evahebsim ot tuoba saw eh dna ,snrettap roivaheb s'OEC eht ezingocer ot demmargorp eb lliw ten ytiruces riehT
.stidercagem ni diap gnitteg ereh pu m’I
edis ym ta spots neht ,em ot gniw revo gniw sbmilc eH
”!niaga em hctac nac uoy fi s’tahT“
?evah yug siht seod eugnot hcum woH
.ton ro uoy hctac I rehtehw ,yenom ruoy tog ev’I
.ruf ym hguorht eson sih sehsup eH
.thgin eht otni kcab sehcnual dna
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.thgiew ym troppus ylraelc nac eH  .deirrow ton m’I
.etadommocca nac I sa htgnel eht fo hcum sa ot desu worg em gnittel—
!eno wen elohw a htiw pu emoc ot evah uoy dna
.secafrus talf no eliga ylralucitrap t’nera staB
.sgnul ym ni sretlif dah t’ndah I fi
.edisni dnah ym tif tsomla nac I egral os era selohyek ehT
.tuo ti llup ot tnaw t’ndid I
,evid naws lufecarg a evah I
.yap s’thginot htiw net rehtona yub dluoc I
.no era sthgil ehT
.em hctac t’now yeht tub
tab a ot pu erusaem ot tliub ton tsuj m’I sseuG
.ksed s’OEC eht otni tliub kcaj retupmoc eht dnif I
.niaga ecaps ytpme revo m’I dna spets eerhT
.lloryap no tab a tog ev’yeht esruoc fO  .tab A
,nepo pans sgniw siH
”!hsur enilanerda na tsuj s’tI“
.erus eb ot doog syawla s’ti tub
.niaga daor eht ssorca flesym elgna I
.gnitib speek eh dna ,gnihsup speek eH
.foor eht fo egde eht no sespalloc eh ,tuo snur eciuj ym nehw dna ,digir seog ydob elohw siH
.em polevne sgniW
.etatsorp ym smals ruhtrA sa sevaw niht ni gniwolf dna
.sgniw sih ni mraw rehtar yllautca s’tI
.tsap sehtycs ti sa gnidliub a dnuora kcud dna tuo level I
,xif txen rieht rof hguone rehtegot eparcs ot tsuj deeps pot ta gnitnirps erew level-teerts ta nwod srennur esoht lla elihw ,yhw s’tahT
.htuom sih fo foor eht yarps I sa esluvnoc I
.ytilibail a eb d’I
?ruf keelS  .yadot saw I tahw em edam taht sloot eht lla em evag ehS
.skeehc pmur ym neewteb sedils eh sa em nevig s’eh serutcnup elpitlum eht skcil eH
.og em stel ruhtrA yltnatculer dna ,hsup I
.niaga kcen ym ta era hteet sih dna
ylivaeh gnihtaerb s’eH
sub a segdod ruhtrA ,em dniheB  !efil si sihT
.teef ym ta sduolC  .niht s’riA
.evruc lufecarg a ni tnecsed ym wols dna ria eht hctac niks fo spalf nihT  .sgel ruof lla dnetxe I   .demood m’I
.toof eraps eno htiw stsirw ym ot sffucdnah tif ot gniyrt t’nsaw eh ylno fI
.sreward sah ksed ehT
.repeed knis hteet sih dna ,erom elggurts I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.esiar a teg neve ll’uoy ebyam dna thgir ti yalp ,lleH
oga sruoh owt daed neeb ev'd'I goms eht htiw dna ,pu selim eerhT
.saw reven tI  .yrassecen t’nsaw tI
,seitiruces procavoN morf tisiv rehtona teg ll’I
”hgiH enilanerdA“ saw sihT
”.wodniw a otni uoy dewolp tsrif I ecnis ti fo gnikeer neeb ev’uoY“
.kcab llup spih sih dna
.regnad a t’nera esohT  .senord
.gnileef siht evol I naM  .staeb traeh yM
.kcab nrut ot ecnahc yreve mih nevig ev’I tuB
.sgelerof ym niartser ot gnilggurts ro ,sffuc fo riap rehtona tif ot gniyrt ton osla s’eh
.nips dellortnocnu na otni em sdnes dna
,niaga mih ees I nehW
.krowkcirb eht no hctac swalc siH  .kcab nael I
”.niaga og ot gnol em ekat t’now ti
.rettam t’nseod tI
.kcab emoc snoitarbiV
ssalg eht tuc sregnif citehtsorP
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.tekcap txen eht no tnes si yreuq ym dna ,knilpu na em stnarg noitcennoc etilletaS
.snac ados rieht fo eno naht regral on egakcap a ni
.htaerb ym hctac ot gnitpmetta m’I sa
,dednecsa neeb neve t’ndah daD
,pit sih revo sdnah ym tup I
.yenom erom tib a mih eriw I
.srosnes noitarbiv era emarf wodniw eht nI  .tcefreP
,thgit em sguh gniw siH
.sgniw tnecrep ytenin tuoba
.doog sleef osla ti tub ,hcum oot s’tI
.ti eciton neve t’nod I
.hcaorppa sduolC
.wohs doog a teg yeht epoh I
.noitnetta suoires emos em teg ot tuoba si selif eseht gnisseccA
.em tfel s’eh dnuow gnideelb eht ta skcil eh sa naom I
niaga elkna ym sehctac walc sih sa sniev ym hguorht gnipmup enilanerda eht s’tI
.ecaf gninepmad ylkciuq ym ta kcil ot htuom ym nepo I
.htaehs sih fo tuo gnikcits s’eH
.mih otno nwod em edils ylwols ytivarg tel dna
.procavoN ta retsor no tab eno ylnO
.dezat tog uoy erofeb raf siht em desahc uoy meht lleT
,mU“   ?dnuora yaw rehto eht ti si rO
.em fo tuo psag a gnicrof
.esion fo aes a ni elbisivni eb llew sa thgim I ,yawa ylf I nehW
.tsael ta rof lufknaht eb ot taht evah I os ,syad eseht tneitnes-
.rof wohs a ekam ot detnaw eh ytic eht dnuora dettod saremac ytiruces latnedicni tsuj saw ti oS
,stneilc thgir eht tih I fi ebyaM
.oot os kniht I  ?doog dnuoS
.em naht reggib s’eH  .htap ym skcolb eh tub
,enal-revoh tsrif eht htaeneb kcud I
.yranilpicsid a neve tuohtiw ffo ti ekam neve thgim uoy tub
.teef ym htaeneb teprac hsulP  .nwod poh I
.pu ti eviG“   ”--yas uoy gnihtynA
.ruhtrA ekil poc a fo rotaderp laer a ecaf ot gniog saw I nwonk d’I fi em htiw thguorb evah dluow I taht rotareneg esion etihw dnab-ediw elttil a evah I dnoceS   .naelc ot sseL
.evlos ot gniog s’ti naht snoitseuq erom gnisiar s’ti
.ten lanretni rieht otni deggol m'I won dna ,procavoN si thginot ytud no mrif ytiruces ehT  .procavoN
,ti ta gnikool m’I taht won tub ,tcepxe ot tahw wonk t’ndid I
.tellub a morf ezarg a ro ,sqnart s’ti yllausU
.woleb ylwols gninnips dlrow eht ta kooL
.edis htron eht raen elit foor nekorb a rednu evah I hsats eht ot revo elddaw I
em dnuora tlits sbmil sih fo eerhT
enim dnuora slruc ydob regral sih elihw neve
.htrae siht fo sdog meht edam wohemos sbmuht fo noissessop rieht dna tcelletni roirepus rieht taht decnivnoc ,snamuh kaew ,dnilb ,faed ,bmuD
,mih ot revo kcab klaw I
.daeh ym fo pot eht tsniaga
.llams oot raf m’I
.edis raf eht morf flesym worht dna potfoor denodnaba eht ssorca tnirps I
,lerdnaK yb ”hgiH enilanerdA“
.goms deifidilos dna slatsyrc retaw hguorht evid I sa skeehc ym ta raet nehT
.ti fo kool eht rof tsuj ,hctam noitibihxe na ,hA
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.duh laniter ym ni pilb A   .eerf m’I
.stsurht eh sa niaga gniylf m’I ekil sleef tI
.niaga snepo neht ,sesolc htuom siH
.eloh prahs eht hguorht gnirepmacs ,ni m’I dna
.rac a egdod ot emit ni tsuj dniw eht ni tuo spalf ym teg I
ixat gniog-wols a hctac I
.enilanerda eht s’tI“
revoc eht otni pid dna tfel eht ot evruc I sa edaf ot strats dniw ehT
.ecnalab sih gniniager saw eh elihw ffo hcnual I
”?5niagAsihTegnahCoTevaHIoDyhW“
.ria thgin eht otni tuo htgnel gnikop nwo ym dna sllab dna pmur dna ruf gnillips ,sgut eH
.gnieb rebmemer reve I naht reffits m’I
.ruoh rep selim ytfif ta tsap gnimaercs riA
.esae htiw enots eht pirg scitehtsorp regnif-okceG
.edilg I sa ruf ym morf knups tab fo sremaerts dna spird sllup dniw ehT
.aedi na s’ereht woN
.yrtne fo tniop thgir eht dnif d’I won yrots ynA
.mih tsniaga elggurts I elihw ffo yreuq txen ym dnes I
”?pu peek nac uoy kniht ,tahW“
.ni kcab sehsup ti naht tuo erom sllup gnitsurht sih dna sedaf gnibborht eht yaw eht ni ti leef nac I  .gninetfos
,epacse ot em rof moor sekam eH
.dniw gnihsur eht evoba skcilc elbidua ,won ranos eht raeh nac I
.emit txen a eb ll’ereht ebyaM  .llew hA
.sdon eH  .ksa I
.xelpmoc tnemtrapa na fo edis eht tsniaga em slian eH
,niaga kcen ym setib eH
”--yas t’ndid I  ?lleh eht tahW“
.lufhtuom sih hguorht shgual eH   ”.kcuf-
.ta tseb m’I tahw s’taht gniht dooG
.sregnif ym htaeneb ssalG
.egagnesid hteet dna
.ytirar a erew sehtolc os ,srobhgien larutan dna sdneirf larutaN
,yrrow t’noD“   ”.oot ti teg I
”.thgin worromot eerf m’I kniht I
”99eMgnigguBpotS“
tneculsnart ssalg eht nwod selbbird tI
.flesmih seidaets eh sa toof ym sehctac walc ekil-kooh A
.rezat erutainim a—
.niarb ym rof nocilis dna ,senob ym rof latem ,sbmil ym rof scinoib ,sdnah ym rof scitehtsorP  .ti htrow saw
.ecneserp sih esnes nac I tub
.em edisni mih leef llits nac I raews I
.sduolc til-rednu eht tsniaga espmilg tsrif ym hctac I
,moolg emit thgin eht hguorht neve elims dezarc sih ees nac I
,ylbisiv sborht eH
.wodniw s’rebmem ecneidua ykculnu eht fo ffo gnihsup m’I
bus eht rof doog os ton s’efiL
”?gniylf er’uoy nehw reggirt riaH“
.sretsnom eivom etihw-dna-kcalb ylrae fo kniht em ekam yletaidemmi t’nseod taht ecaf a htiw seno yzzuf eht fo eno ,xof gniylf a s’eH
.stiderc noillim evif tniop owT
.noitaitogen a s’ti—
,sniarb slamina diputs su evag yehT
,eromyna hguone doog t’nsi tsuj drowssap dlo ruoy taht uoy llet yeht
.tius ym ot ecived eht gnihcatta
.msagro yrd a s’ti ebyaM
.spmuj hgih rof sgel ym ni srotautca deriw-drah evah I wonk t’nseod eH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.nuJ flesym llac I
.revo dekconk eb ton ot ecarb ot evah I
,tnorf eht nwod deppiznu neeb sah mrofinu siH
.tnorf ym nwod tigid-gniw egnarts sih sgard gniw thgir sih elihw
.siht ekil fo tros ,lleW
.repmacs dna nrut I
,hctac ot nacs ym rof llams oot ,srotceted noitom rellams rehto ylbaborp s’erehT
.em ees ,deedni ,did ti taht em smrofni erawtew laruen ym tub ,hctac ot srae ym rof kciuq oot dna tfos oot s’tI  .kcilC  .kcilC
,thgieh siht morF
.ehtaerb t’nac I  .dnapxe t’now sgnul yM  .em raeh t’nseod eh ,tsap gnitsug dniw eht htiW  .ezeehw I  ”,ruhtrA“   .ehcilc eripmav elohw eht seog ereht ,lleW
.sllab ym htaeneb nwod spid dna kcoc ym tsniaga sedils eugnot siH
.mih rof ksed lluf eht evah ot ton fi ,yraterces a yap eh did yhW
.skcol cinortcele naht rehtar selohyek dlo sah ti tub ,dekcol er’yehT
.nedlog m’I  .tuo m’I
.daeh sih ssik dna nwod hcaer I
.sreparcsyks dlo htiw dettod
.ti droffa nac I erus ton m’I fi sa—
.krow ot eugnot sih stup dna nwod snael eH
”--ton er’uoY  .poc ,ffo kcuF“
.eno naht syaw erom ni—
.thgir nrut I  .tunlaW dna htfiF
.secafretni eht pu kooh ot rehtona neht
.enim s'ti dna ,ti ecnuonorp neve t'nac I ,lleH  .nujtnujtrrajD  .morf erew ew erehw noiger eht ot evitan saw dias ehs eman a em nevig neve d'ehS
.tuo pils yllanif pit sih leef I sa ti gnitterger fo tros yllaer m’I
.kcor reehs eht pu gnilacs ,mih htaeneb morf tuo lwarc I
.niarb ym ot nwod m’I sseuG  .seilf eh tub
.gnivig no speek taht tfig eht si tab siht ,nam hO
.keew tsal eht nihtiw etad eriH
.eerf sborht eh neht dnA
.em hctac reve dluoc taht
.tius eht edisni deppart teg ti evah naht rehtar ,tib a ria ti tel I fi retteb ylbaborp s’ti ,yllautcA  .pots neht
.gnibborht s’eh nehT
.emit deen tsuj I  .emiT
,em dnuorrus sgniw siH
noisiv ym smid saniter detnalpmi ym ni noitasnepmoc citamotuA  .seralf thgiL
,sgniw sih fo teknalb eht ni em srevoc eh dna niaga dnal I nehW
.gnitnuoc dna pu selim eerhT   lerdnaK yb
.tnorf nwo sih tsniaga gnippals dna hcamots ym morf gnitfil
.yregrus eht ogrednu ot dediced I erofeb tnacifingis t’nerew stnelat larutan ym yas ot toN
.lluf dnoyeb dna ot em sllif hsur toh A
.radal dna radar yb dewollof ,sgnip ranoS
.teknalb gnitcirtsnoc ,thgit a ekil em sguh gniw eerf eno dna
,dne elbaresim sti ot niahc eht wollof I   .niaga dnA  .niagA
.aedi rehtona evah I
.pit mils sih dnuora em sdaerps eh nehw ssalg eht no raems a evael I
”.ydaerla tnuocca ruoy nI  .stiderc dnasuoht evif ytnewt s’tahT“   ”…tahT“   .digir seog nehT
.tnuocca knab ym dna niarb ym ot nwod m’I  :noitcerroC
seirots s’lerdnaK fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,tenalPruF yb
?resu dne-wol a tog ev’uoy nehw erawtfos gnikcah dne-hgih htiw rehtob yhW  .ni m’I
?mid saw I kniht uoy diD“
.dekcajih d’I tnuocca tahw rettam t’ndid tI
hgiH enilanerdA:yojne esaelP
.thgit gnidloh m’I tub ,spalf ym sehctac dniW
”.sedaced rof lagel neeb t’nsah tihs tahT
,redro lacigolonorhc esrever ni degnarra llA
.seye ym esolc I
.nihc sih rednu pu thgir eson ym kcits I
.ytic rehtona ot refsnart a em yub dluow yenom tramS
,niaga spord ti nehT
.eciwt ekam t’now eh ekatsim a s’tahT
.krowkcirb fo tib gnignahrevo na fo
.tsirw ym no moc lanosrep ym teg ll’eh
.gnidliub a fo xepa eht ot kcab teef ytnewt sdrawpu em sllup dna spalf ym sehctac tfardpu nA
.su neewteb tsap smaercs kcurt A
.sgel sih htiw em eruces dna pu lwarc ot emit eht sesu eh tub ,llafeerf otni su fo htob sworht tI
.ygolocrA rewoT ailongaM dnuora erehwyreve was I sreklaw-niks roop eht no pmuj eht dah I ydaerla os
.tuo yrc I nehw kcen ym setib eH
sgel ruof no eciffo roolf htderdnuh-enin ruoy otni kaerb t’ndid eganoipse etaroproc nehw ,tsap eht ni sraey ytnewt kcuts llits sevitucexe diputS
.daeh sih dnuora sregnif ym parw dna pu hcaer I
.htaehs sih revo gnippird dna shgiht ym tsniaga tuo gnihsug ti leef nac I
,mih fo hcum os s’erehT
.sesuohtnep gnirewot eht neewteb ni edilg tsaf a otni nips liat ym llup dna sreparcsyks tsehgih eht woleb pid I sa
.em dnuora sdnal ruhtrA
.nwod ecnalg I dna sezzub tsirw yM
.yap kcajoinarc ym rof srotcennoc dlog dna sgnirrae dnomaiD  .yap yeht dnA
.ti ta kool esolc a teg nac I os sgel ym neewteb pu mih llup I sa srae ym smoorg eH
.pu tuhS“   ”.snikneJ ruhtrA
.hguoht ,siht nialpxe ot gniog m’I woh erus ton m’I  .ylsuoires
.sdraob gnidloffacs fo edam ecafrus latnoziroh a otno em sllor eh emit sihT
.tif ot elba neeb ev’I swonk niarb lanoitar ym tib elttil eht tsuj naht rehtar ,em fo lla hguorht gnipmuh s’eh ekil sleef ti
,nworg neeb d’yeht yaw eht sgniht detnaw reve ylnO
ecaf sih no esirprus fo kool eht hctac I
.llat seirots thgie dna dnasuoht lla
.ylleb ym fo pot eht ot thgiarts pu skcits ti dna ,ti dnuora tif ot sdnah ym fo htob sekat tI  .lleh gnikcuF
,llorknab etaroproc a ni gnillup ton er’uoy fi dnA
.pord reve fo em deniard s’eh litnu og tel t’nseod eH  .dnik s’eH
ssalg denekrad eht hguorht resal ttawolik teloivartlU
”.dnik os eb dluow uoy fi ,DUH ruoy kcehc ,ruhtrA“
?tihs laets uoy od netfo woH  .oS“
”?gnikniht I saw tahW  .em fo yllis woH“
!ti nrae attog uoy tuB
.ni neddih d’I pag eht otni nwod edispu sgniws eh ,swalc fo elbbarcs a htiW
.sdirbyh diputs tuo emoc evah thgim ew ro
.spots eh nehw ecnesba sih leef yleros I tub ,ereht nwod s’eh gnol woh wonk t’nod I
.niaga em revo selppir ranos sih emit emas eht ta
.kcen ym setib dna drawrof snael eh ,niaga elggurts ot trats I nehW
.gnipsag m’I sa gnidliub dnoces a otni em smals eH
.liat ym htaeneb tsuj reppiz eht sehctac walc delruc sih dna
rof dengised saw I tahw s’tI
.tifeneb ruoy rof si yllaer siht tub ,ruhtrA yrroS“
.niaga drah s’eH
!tneinevnocni woH
.rebif nobrac dna nocilis dna latem ni niaga nrob gnieb yb dnoces dna
,mir etercnoc eht no tis I
,foor eht no neddih hsats a evah I ,sulP
.elddup a otni nwod kool I
.tsirw ym kcehc I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.em hctac ot tliub t’nsaw tsuj ytiruces dlo riehT
.edam saw tnemeerga tnelis eht nehw erus ton m’I
.gnippird llits yletinifed m’I ,oN
,raf siht em deirrac ev'yehT
.yks eht otni hgih gnirewot seigolocra eht yb pu nekorb
.em teem ot pu esir salegnA weN fo serips eldeen tnatsid eht dna
,hself eht ni nrob gnieb yb tsrif—
.spalf fo ekud eht m’I
.eganoipse etaroproc rof enoyna tsuj erih t’ndid yehT
?reh ekil neg-tsrif a morf tcepxe uoy nac tahW
,krowten mart eht fo sliar desiar eht dna ciffart revoh fo reyal pot eht neewteB
.yap ngiapmahc citehtnys rengised dna raivac derb-tav muimerP
lareF ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw yrots ehT
.niaga ruf ym sehsurb ranoS  .elohssA
?tab siht fo lla tif ot desoppus I ma erehw ,lleH
ffo sffuc sih resal ot em rof hguone gnol s’ti tub ,gnol tsal t’nseod modeerF
.sraey rof no evivrus ot hguone si tuoyap sihT
.stoob tekcor teg rO
”.og uoy tel tsuj t’nac llits I wonk uoY“
.dedeen I gninepo eht em sevig sffuc eht htiw gnilbmuf siH
,eno tsehgih eht neve htiw level ward I erofeB
,emit htnoillim eht roF
.enal txen eht revo pilf ot mutnemom eht esu dna
si yrots s’yadot dna
.ffo kcik dna ecaf sih no toof a tup I  .rekcuF
.lanoisseforp gnikcuf a m’I esuaceb
.”enOweNAekaMoTeMgnilleTpotSoSeroMrOsretcarahC52sIsihT“
?lla ti peek eh seod erehW
.elbat s’OEC eht htaeneb der gnihsalf ydaerla si mrala tnelis tsrif eht
.rehtona yub tsuj nac I rO
.guh sih otni flesym nael I
.won hcir m’I ,lleH
em sdloh gniw siH
.em droffa t’nac uoy ,on
.eb dluohs ti woh si sihT  .hgual I
.ciffart edutitla wol fo seralg gnidnilb eht yb detautcnup
.tnemtrapa esuohtnep s’enoemos fo wodniw ssalg eht otni edilloc ew sa em morf dekconk si htaerb neht ,llafeerf fo tnemom rehtona s’erehT
.niaga drah m’I esuaceb ,cimanydorea tsom ym ta ton m’I
.kcoc fo sehcni elohw ekil sleef tahw yb dewollof s’tI
.eussit tew ot yldneirf ytic a ton saw salegnA weN
.sezeeuqs eugnot siH   .driht eht rO
.tsehc ym revo nwod spird dna nihc ym fo edisrednu eht stih hsalps dnoces A
.tekramyaH eht fo llaw eht ot edilg I
.mih ta kcab ecnalg I
sllehcyas-eht-ni-sdnekeew-dna-tej-lanosrep retsim roop nehw yltneuqerf erom yllanoisacco dna
.em edisni naht rehtar sgel ym neewteb ria eht ni gnihctiwt tnaig gnibborht taht fo flah eb tsum erehT  .nwod kool I
.demmid era swodniW
.em dniheb pu gnihsup mih leef nac I dna
,ydob ym sevom ti taht gnorts os si gut ehT
.ranoS  .kcilC  .kcilC
.ti sraeh eh emit tahT
,regnorts dna ,retsaf ,retrams er’ew won dna
yleritne llaw eht fo og tel I
htiw metsys eht otni gol neht
.sreparcsyks redlo eht fo level eht ot nwod won er’eW
,yawyna ti gniraew m’I tub
.scitehtsorp niks-okceg dednob htiw deppit era sregniF  .ylsseltroffE
.tuo gnidils peek dnA
,kcab ym hsalps sehctiwt fo elpuoc tsal siH
.evivrus ot tnaw t’nod I tuB
,dah ydaerla I tahw decnahne tsuj scitenrebyc ym llA
.nur gnol eht ni erom htrow ebyam tuB
.ytic eht otni tuo gnikool
.ti gnitterger m’I taht toN
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
?taht fo lla tif ot em gnitcepxe eh si erehw ,elpmaxe roF
,egnahcxe salegnA weN thgir eht otni taht sepyt eh fi esuaceB
.thguac eb reven tsuJ  .od ll’I tahw s’taht kniht I
”?em tsurt uoy od ,ruhtrA“
.eurt gnimoc pots dluow saipotsyd erutuf sih sehsiw yllaer ohw
”.seivom poc ynam oot hctaw uoy ,ruhtrA ,ekas s’kcuf roF“   ”.drocer
.nwodekat hguor sih htiw tnedicca etanutrofnu na tem evah tsum tI
.hcaorppa sih no sllats eH
.srae ym ni repsihw a ekil sdnuos gnituohs sih neve ,su dnuora gniraor tfardpu eht htiW
.thginot dedeen ton era slliks ruoY  .rezat raed ,thgit peelS
.pu kcab llup ot emit evah I ,yako s’tI
.ciffart woleb ffo edilg I sa em morf gnippird llits gnilf gnizama eno dna muinarc ym ni atadyap fo setybatez owt tniop ruoF
.noitalusni larutan ti llac I
.kaep nwo sih hguorht thgiarts spmuh eh sa
etatiseh ot doog skool tI  .etatiseh I
.elbaifitnedi oot eb dluow doolB
.esolc si liat ym no si reveohW
.dniheb morf sllab sih sserac dna nwod hcaer I
,hguorht m’I dnoces a nI
.tuo ees nac enoyna fi wonk t’noD
,tcennocsid I nehW
,muc tsuj ev’I hguoht nevE
.sgnidliub fo spot eht yb noitacol ym erugif nac I taht won level dnuorg ot hguone esolc m’I
.modeerf ybraen sdrawot edilg dna
.thgin eht otni flesym hcnual I nehT
.sretpada kcaj-itlum erew kcapkcab ym nI
,foor eht hctac ot edutitla hcum oot tsol ev’I
.gnippird llits m’I kniht I
.noom on htiw thgin krad a s’tI  .erac t’noD
.ytpme yletelpmoc saw ti ,yalpsid rotinomoloh eht naht rehtO
,noitca evisave rof sgelerof ym elgna I
.erofeb tab a dah reven ev’I
tsoc dah ti revetahW
.em ta pu gnilims s’eH
mih tsniaga liat ym hctiwt I
.hsup dna tuo teg ot evah d’I ,retsaf yna og ot tnaw I fI
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ecnahc a doots reven I  .setarbiv tahT
.siht ekil snoitautis rof tsuj peek I tik elttil a tcartxe I tsriF
.gnir evitisnes ym hguorht sih fo retsnom taht sedils dna
.meht ,loof eht erom ,lleW
.rewot eht fo pot eht stih ti erofeb gnitareleced ylbidua
.ruhtrA“   ”--tub ,eman ym wonk uoy woh ro era uoy ohw wonk t’nod I“
.snemiceps ooz naht erom ylerab ,elarutan-ua sredilg ragus neeb dah stnerap reH
lloryap no tog ev’yeht poc ylno eht dna
.niP noitacifitnedI snezitiC sih tog ev’I
,sraey rof erutcurts leets lateleks a tsuj neeb s’tI
.yrots driht-ythgie-dna-htderdnuh-enin eht no ma I ereH
.srae sih revo sdnah ym gard I
.eltneg s’eh ,emit sihT
.reylf retteb a si tab eht tub ,tsaf m’I
.eman sih sraeh eh nehw esool ti spord dna selbmuf eh tub
,pael I erofeb tub ,egde s’foor eht ot nrut I
.thgieh eht s’tI  .hsur eht s’tI
.gniw sih rednu kcud I
.llol daeh ym tel dna seye ym esolc I
.strams eht thguac slamina eht lla dna ,deneppah proc-irgA nehT
wonk su fo htob dna ,sllaw renni ym fo evruc a tsniaga hsup mih leef I nehT