Ő.noitca ymene si semit eerhT
tuBÔ .kcab denael dna smra sih dedlof nitraM
.cificeps oot teg tŐndluow yeht depoh eh ,rehto hcae ot deklat yeht fI
.snialliv yb nwod tup selzzup gnivlos erew yeht
.ecnahc dnoces a htiw cennef eht pleh ot hguone citehtapmys neeb dah nitraM dna
,ebyam tsuj ,ebyam dna ,elbisualp yletomer saw taht dnif dluoc eh noitanalpxe ylno eht saw tahT
Ő.worromot mih txet
.srae sŐkriK ni htmraw eht esaerced ot gnihton did yniturcs ehT
,tcnitsni rieht detsurt syawla seipS
Ő.taht fo
elbat tnecajda na morf riahc desunu na koot ynnoL .erew yehT
.part sih tes ot su desu
.lla meht detsurt I dias evŐdluow I oga skeew
.dnuora gnikaens dna gniyl siht lla od ot evah tŐndluow uoyÔ ,dias nitraM Ő,ecalp tsrif eht ni taht enod tsuj dŐuoy fIÔ
Ő.doirep gninruom eht ni llits sŐeh ,revetahWÔ Ő.skeew
.ti derongi kriK tub
Ő.elpmas dluoc uoy kniht I kcart eno sŐerehT
Ő.tnaw uoy nosrep eht sŐtaht
Ő.tuo ti erugif mih teL ?erac uoy od
,dab si uoy no gniyps dneirfyob-xe ruoy kniht uoy fi dna scitilop truoc lacirotsih gniyduts mŐI sulp dna
hOÔ .denettalf srae sŐkriK Ő.oNÔ
.uoy rof emit sekam eh os mih ot tnatropmi era syug uoy wonk I dna
,sreksihw sih fo gniggas eht ,srae sŐcennef eht fo gninettalf eht wenk eH
.ma IÔ Ő.suoires eb
Ő.htnom a rof elgnis neeb ylno sŐyug ehT
teg thgim siht ekil
,sdrow sih revo elbmuts nitraM gnihctaw nuf elttil a saw tI
.sah eh kniht t'nod
,llam eht dna ,eivom eht ta pu dewohs eH .tfel eh
smeeSÔ .kcab riahc sih dehsup ynnoL
riahc sih rednu ylthgit delruc liat sih dna kcab srae sih
annoGÔ .denettalf srae sih sa eugnot denedder a htiw iriuqiad sih pu gnippal ,derettum nitraM
,gnikooLÔ Ő.syug rehto ta kool tsael ta ton dna ereh emoc tsuj tŐnac
tuBÔ .dias kriK Ő,suoitneterp fo edis siht tsuj sŐtekcaj
Ő.syug rehto htiw ecnad ot mih teg ot gniyrt erew uoy yhw sŐtahTÔ .dias ynnoL
eht dna
ysub laer eb annog saw I dias I ,naem
,rood eht hguorht deklaw atroP sa ezorf meht fo htob os dna
Ő.eulc a evah tŐnod uoYÔ
,rood kcab eht ni emoc evah tsum eH
roolf ecnad eht ta ,mih tsap tub
,rennid thgin yadsendeW ylkeew a dah ydaerla yehT
IÔ Ő?taht od I dluow yhW
,nees dŐyeht seivom fo stcepsa esoht gnissucsid deyojne yllausu yeht os ,egelloc ni ngised retaeht ni dekrow dah kriK dna
?naV tnorfnoc dna revo og tsuj ton yhwŃ
.deppots eh erofeb ŐŃkniht uoy did tahw oSÔ ,sa raf sa tog ylno eh
.revo eb dŐti renoos eht ,did eh renoos eht tub
.yhw enigami mih fo efil eht rof ton dluoc eh tub
,owt ro yad txen eht ni erehwemos rehtegot gnitteg si puorg eht taht meht llet dluohs uoy
fIÔ .deppans eltsimocac eht Ő,tluaf ruoy
tŐnaCÔ .etunim a rof pu sgniht kool ot dedneterp dna enohp sih tuo koot eH
Ő.neht syug uoy
,pu swohs naV reverehW
,sepirCÔ .knird sih ta nwod gnirats llits dna
nitraM drawot wap derruf-wolley a tuo dehcaer ynnoL Ő.edud ,sknahT
ÓenozdneirF tnegAŇ
,naem I .mih ot klat llŐI ,koolŃfI
.gnihtemos ro egassem txet ro tcejbus liame na sa pu dne dluow seltit gnos eht fo eno erew secnahc ,tuo taht dnuof cennef eht fI
tŐnoDÔ  .reh dniheb llaw eht no gnignah sllorcs oobmab eht fo tsom tuo gnikcolb
fo dnuor a hguorht tis ot gnitnaw ton ,ti otno drac sih dessot dna
,ti taeper ot denrut eh nehw tub
.mih rof detrats noissucsid taht evah ot evah tŐndid ohw enoemos dedeen kriK taht dna
,suoucipsnocni flesmih ekam ot gniyrt saw eh dna
fiÔ ,dias atroP
uoYÔ .teef reh ot retto eht gnillup ,doots dna daeh sih koohs eH Ő.su sewo eH
rood eht drawot ylkciuq denrut eltsimocac ehT
Ő.em ot tuo detniop meht deen tŐnod I .erus
?ti did ,hguoht ,nialliv a mih ekam tŐndid yps a part ot gniyrT
,raugaj eht tub ,yltnatsnoc dehctiwt eson sŐynnoL
IÔ Ő?egassem txet revo mih htiw pu kaerb ot gniog
ŐŃesuaceb naV htiw pu kaerb ot em teg ot gniyrt neeb sŐnitraMÔ .detsisni kriK
naVÔ .ffo mih tuc nitraM tub ,klat ot detrats eH
owTÔ ,yas ot hguone gnol daeh sih detfil nitraM
.ediS tseW eht ni revo rab wen siht yrt ot tnaw
.gnihtemos ro ,ylroop flesmih gnisserpxe
hOÔ .deilper nitraM ,denrut-flah kriK sa noos sa tub
llAÔ .gnilims ,daeh reh koohs aiM
Ő.mubla wen ŐsdahalaG eht tuoba klat dluohs ew ebyam dna enif erŐuoy ylraelc
,sruoh rof gnitca klat dluoc nitraM
,emarf rood eht dnoyeb tsuj gnivaw liat deppit-etihw kciht sih
,mih was I taht was eh sa noos sa tub
.sleef kriK woh noitseuq tŐnodŃ
. Éniaga enoemos htiw pu mih kooh ot gniyrt detrats nitraM fI Ő.hOÔ
.mraw tlef elzzum sŐkriK Ő.wonk tŐnod
.ylreporp ti yojne tŐndluoc kriK tub
,slevon dna seirots sih rof drawA ltoyoC a dna sdrawa rojaM asrU evlewt now sah ohw
,kool retteb a teg ot kcab denael kriK
.rehto eht ot edis eno morf denrut kriK ŐŃ
,ta gnivaw saw kriK ohw ees ot denrut nitraM
?won mih gnihctaw ereht tuo eb naV dluoC
,smoor reteiuq owt ni ecivres elbat dna
,deppans kriK Ő,og ti
Ő,oNÔ Ő?mih etad ot tnaw uoy
lleTÔ Ő.oot od uoy ,mih llet ot evah I fIÔ Ő.kriKÔ
.ti ekam ot elba eb ton thgim eh dias dna azzip eht erofeb os ro ruoh na ynnoL dellac eh oS
,laed a gib taht tŐnsaw ti taht yllautcelletni wenk eh fi nevE
,thguoht dah kriK sa ,ynnoL no ton saw ezag sŐnitraM
tuBÔ .liatkcoc sih deppis eltsimocac ehT Ő.tŐnod
aHÔ Ő.nwod tohs teg uoy nehw ereh eb llits lliw I dna ynnoL
?mih ot klat dna ereht revo og yllautneve dŐeh naV deciton eh fi ,ekiL
aiMÔ .daeh reh koohs atroP
,krow ni deirub saw kriK taht yas ot tsuj meht txet ro srehto eht fo rehtie llac ot ylekil tŐnsaw ynnoL
,wap sih tsniaga daeh sih detser kriK
Ő?thgir ,mih htiw pu kaerb yllautca did
ew era eno hcihw ,secalp tnereffid su dlot uoy ,yeHÔ ,gniyas meht fo eno morf egassem a ees ot detcepxe eh
,detsaot kriK Ő.looCÔ
mŐIÔ .daeh reh koohs atroP
woHÔ .kriK rof rab eht ta syug etuc tuo gnikcip ot kcab tnew nitraM ,deggalf noitasrevnoc eht nehw tuB
oslAÔ .daeh reh koohs aiM
,naV htiw tneps sgnineve fo esac cificeps eht ni eurt saw hcihw
?ecnereffid a ekam taht seod yhw ,yawynaŃ
.tnaem eh tahw teg ot gnol oot ekat naV gnihctaw nuf dna
IÔ Ő?thgir ,dneterp ot nuf sŐti
.mih htiw ylisaenu tas yeht
,yadirF dna yadsruhT fo tser eht revo dnuof eh ,epoH
noitcerid sih ni detniop srae egral fo riap a fo thgis thguac eh redluohs sŐnitraM revo tub
tsuJÔ .desuap tub ,ssalg sih detfil kriK
rettiwT no mih wollof nac uoy dna
emit eht lla secalp fo hcnub a ot tuo gniog sŐeh ebyaM
Ő?pu siht tilps ot gniog ew era wohÔ
esuaceBÔ .sdrow sŐkriK derongi nitraM
.oNÔ Ő.gnihtyna yas ot evah tŐnod uoY .hguone mih htiw tuo gnuh
?rab rehtona atroP dna ynnoL llet uoy didŃ
Ő,doog ytterp era ereh sreeb
sIÔ Ő.strihs wen emos em teg ot detnaw ynnoL dna elas a gnivah erew R&CÔ .delwocs kriK
Ő.letni ti llac
.etunim a ni ereh tsafkaerb teg og attog I ,kool ,thgir
mŐIÔ Ő.gnihtyna gniod tŐnerew uoYÔ .mih dlot atroP Ő,dessap uoy esruoc fOÔ Ő!dessap I
tahWÔ .tnelis eltsimocac eht devaw kriK
dŐyehTÔ Ő.yhw dna naV ot gniklat si meht fo yna fi meht ksa dna pu tuN
?retal seussi pihsnoitaler ym ssucsid ew
.cipot taht no ruoh na flah dellik llits yeht
Ő?gnihtyna htiw od ot evah siht seod tahW
.naV ot klat
teLÔ Ő?xof eht ,yug taht tuoba
?suoires uoy eraŃuoy erA
.dekrow ti tubŃtub
.9102 hguorht snoisses sti fo hcae ta detcurtsni sah dna ,pohskrow gnitirw yrruf laitnediser tsrif eht ,RWAR
sŐtIÔ Ő?em no yps ot erehw mih gnillet uoy era rO
oSÔ .taorht reh deraelc atroP
,enot sih detaredom dah nitraM sA
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.hOÔ Ő.rab a tsuJÔ Ő?rab yag a
,derettum nitraM
.oSÔ ŐŃsdrow eht dias uoy
.nalp sih esrever tsuj dŐeh
IÔ .riahc sih ni detfihs kriK Ő.mih dlot
tŐnoDÔ .daeh reh koohs retto llams ehT
diDÔ .drawrof denael atroP
si yrots sŐyadot dna
.atroP dna ynnoL ot denrut eh os
.sserdda eht syug uoy txet llŐI .ti dnif
.kriKÔ .ediw tnew seye sŐeltsimocac ehT
erŐuoYÔ .htaerb a koot kriK Ő.oNÔ
Ő!dekrow tiŃkool
.revo erŐew em dlot tŐnsah ehŃtŐnsah eh tuB
?uoy era erehw ,ereh erŐeW
ebyaMÔ .daeh reh koohs aiM
fIÔ .ecnalab rof liat kciht reh gnisu dna riahc reh gnippit ,kcab denael atroP
tIÔ ,dias aiM sa nottub ŐpU gnaHÔ der eht no gnikcilc ydaerla saw eH
,revo dehcnuh eh oS
,haeYÔ .taorht sih deraelc dna ,dias nitraM
.wohemos pu dewercs dŐeh taht ,tluaf sŐkriK lla saw ti taht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK mŐI
efil laer ni ffuts yps fo dnik siht od tŐnod elpoep ,kriK ,doG ym hO
Ő,hhAÔ Ő.degilbo tŐnsah kriK raf os tub ,ebyam ,pu gnikaerb tuoba klat tsael ta ro esle enoemos htiw ecnad kriK ees ebyam dluoc eh os ,tuo gnignah erŐew erehw naV gnillet neeb
.unem sih ta gnirats ,dias eh
,reklats sih morf yawa ydob sih denrut
Ő?uoy no erusserp tup reve I did nehW
,atroP ot txen elbat eht ssorca gnittis
IÔ .dennirg atroP Ő.tnemgduj
IÔ .yrassecen yltcirts naht reduol ,deksa regdab eht
Ő?pirt aiglatson loohcs hgih a siht saW
,gnippans tuoba dab tlef neht dna
,ebyaMÔ .rab eht ni deyats dah naV sa gnol sa tuoba mih htiw deniamer emehcs sih fo sseccus eht ni tlef dah kriK edirp ehT Ő?part a siht saW
,knird nwo sih deppis kriK
.ylkciuq dessap nitraM htiw sknird fo ruoh flah tsrif ehT
?gnihtemos yas uoy tŐndid yhw ,nitraM
,wonk uoy os
sAÔ Ő.tlef evah dŐI diputs woh enigamI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
sŐtiÔ ,elbat eht deniojer atroP dna eh nehw dias ynnoL Ő,esoppus
,tiaWÔ .rewsna eht fo remmilg a tog
nehTÔ Ő.ti otni gnidaer erŐuoY .skoob yps ynam oot daer
,moc.dloglleyk.www ta elbaliava si
,yakOÔ .htaerb a koot eH
dnAÔ Ő.oot yrros mŐIÔ .tuo dehcaer dna
yps gniyalp dna dnuora gnikaens dna sdneirf ruoy ot gniyl
,ekiLÔ .yawa selbat wef a tsuj srae cennef egral eht fo erawa
,pmal taeh a ekil yniturcs sŐnaV tlef eh erom eht
.dnim ot emac gnihton tub
.wOÔ Ő.tes erŐuoy nehw kcab su evaw syug
;taht ot tpada dluoc kriK tub
Ő.metsys ruoy fo tuo krow attog uoy ffuts emoS
,ybraen gnittis dneirfyob-xe eht ot ecnerefer rehtruf tuohtiw noitasrevnoc eht fo tser eht detagivan eH
Ő.yaw taht tuo ti erugif llŐI .tnaillirb
reh rof edam dŐeh omed lacisum a gniyalp saw
etaerc depleh eH
mih ot kcab emac ecivda sŐaiM
Őmeht fo eno eb ot tog sŐtI
.noitcaer reh no tnetni saw dna
,tnemugra na tsael ta ro ,enecs a eb dŐereht neht dna mih tnorfnoc dna revo emoc thgim eh neht dna
!thgin rehto eht pu wohs ton thgim uoy dias uoy yhw
Ő.ecaf ym ot em dlot tŐnsah eH
.draehrevo gnieb dnim tŐndid eh stcejbus ot noitasrevnoc eht peek ot erus edam dna
Ő.era ew erehw swonk naV taht yaw rehto yna tuo erugif tŐnac I tuB
Ő,htnom a tsomla neeb sah ti
leef I taht naV htiw enod eb ot feiler a hcus sŐti yltsenoh tub ,yepom mŐI ,pihsnoitaler a fo tuo teg I nehw yllausu wonk
.ot gninetsil yltnerruc saw eh mubla tahw sa lanosrep sa neve gnihtyna raehrevo tŐndluow naV taht os wol eciov sih gnipeek
.snosaer fo rebmun yna rof bat eht pu dekcip semitemos meht fo hcae
,rof seivom dnoB ot tnew uoy tahw erew ngised tes ron gnitca rehtien elihw dna
mih nees dŐeh taht wonk dluow naV
.iriuqiad yrrebwarts tnargarf a ni deirub tnemom eht rof saw
IÔ .sreksihw sih revo wap rehto sih debbur eH
Ő.seYÔ Ő.skcus knup-
.nwod esle enoemos gnittel saw eh esuaceb traeh sŐkriK otni yaw sti demrow taht tliug eht
toNÔ Ő?emit eht lla tteS ehT ot og uoy
moor retnec         eht ni rab a dna cisum duol htiw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil erŐuoY
.aedi sŐraugaj eht neeb dah ti dna
Ő,eruSÔ Ő.hguoht ,uoy fo eerht eht tsuj htiw ti gniees ot drawrof gnikool yllaer
sŐtIÔ Ő.wonk I ,ti tuoba gniraeh fo derit era syug
Ő,oSÔ .ekib sih tfel dŐeh erehw kcar ekib eht ot teerts eht nwod dedaeh ynnoL
,tnemmoc sih ot gnitcaerrevo saw naV taht
.skrow ti woh aedi on tog I ,selur nwo ruoy tog syob yag uoY
IÔ .daeh sih dekcud ohw ,eltsimocac eht nwod erats ot ylluf elzzum etihw-dna-kcalb sih denrut eH
tŐnoDÔ .atroP ot ylbamuserp ,mih dniheb devaw raugaj
,laem rieht otni ruoh na flah dnA
Ő.si fo tros ti tub ,em sŐti ,uoy ton sŐti yas ot bmud sdnuos
.citsacras gnieb saw I
,nwod srae rieht dedlof yeht sselnu taht ta dab yllaer erew seiceps derae-gib tub
.haeYÔ Ő?stnuocca sŐesle enoyreve kcehc
.dluoc regdab eht erofeb ekops dna
.eruSÔ ,dias atroP Ő?thgin yadirF
.noitasrevnoc rieht ni tseretni tsol dah elpoep
Ő.yeHÔ .delggig nitraM Ő.on
Ő.mih no pu gnuh llits erŐuoy skniht eh oS
.dias kriK Ő,haey
.emit eht lla
.oNÔ .denethgiarts kriK Ő.oNÔ
,lla ni lla ,tuo gnineve dab a tŐnsaw tI
.keew tsal meht ot no em denrut
.wef tnecer rehto eht ot ti gnirapmoc
,sih tem seye sŐkriK
ehTÔ ŐÓ.spihsnoitaler evah tŐnseod ohw yug tahtŇ ot decuder gnieb ekil I
.yltcaxe yps retsam a ton ,llewŃ
.ti tuoba sdneirf sih fo yna llet tŐndluoc eh dna
Ő.ti timda reven
,snalp detacilpmoc sih gninoitseuq sdneirf sih fo yna tuohtiw dessap syad eht tuB Ő?ta gniteem
,ot neeb reven dŐyeht
.rehtegot gnitteg rof emit emas eht gnittes
.mih ot pu ylraelc saw ti tub
?ti tŐndid ,dekrow
kriKÔ .mra sih no wap a tup atroP Ő.noL ,pu
.ynnoL ,taerg saw ti thguoht
,yrros mŐI ,naV .enif
esuaceBÔ Ő?taht fo kniht tŐndid I emoc woH
,wodniw epykS llams eht pu dellif raeb ralop ehT
eHÔ Ő.ruoh na flah rof gnitiaw erew ew tub ecalp ecin a sŐtI
erŐyehTÔ .deksa kriK Ő?ereh ni mih
;ŐsknahTÔ tpecxe gnihtyna dias ydoboN
.rehtegot knard nitraM dna eh dna
.god dna srentrap sih htiw emoh gniyats yltnerruc si dna ainrofilaC ni sevil eH
.9002 fo levoN yaG tseB rof drawA wobniaR eht now-oc "noitisoP fo tuO" levon demialcca sih dna
Ő?atroP ,kniht uoy
,dworc a ni tsol gnieb fo gnileef eht
,sgnirehtag rieht fo eno no tuo gniklaw tuoba dezisatnaf kriK
,elihw a ni ecno hguorht sgniht kniht ot eganam did ohw ,kriK dnA
naCÔ .tseretni rieht esiugsid ot woh tuo derugif dŐyeht tsael ta rO
.yas yeht tahw ees ,meht yb ti nur
IÔ .drawrof denael ynnoL
.bulc a ot ssa ym teg dna tiftuo thgit a no tup ot em sekat ti sa gnol sa si doirep gninruom yM .em ksa
.did cennef eht gnihtemos od ot detnaw tŐndah kriK emit yreve erew yeht ekil truh htiw thgirb seye sŐnaV gniees tpek eh ,dnim sih ni taht gniod derutcip kriK sa tubŃ
IÔ Ő.uoy ta dehgual evah dluow doirep odE eht fo srorepme eht ,uoy llet em tel
uoYÔ   ***   .elbisnopser saw meht fo eno taht detcepsus eh ,rehtona roF
.tiaWÔ ?reklats a fo hcum taht eh saW
tuBÔ .gniyas saw kriK gnihtyreve ot netsil ot denoitisop srae sih htiw unem sih yduts ot gnidneterp
mŐIÔ .citamard taht gnihtemos od reve tŐndluow eh gniwonk
,revo mih devaw kriK .ti dennacs dna rab eht otni deklaw ynnoL
tuhSÔ .dias kriK Ő?ÓteGŇÔ Ő.lanosrep
?ti gniod eh sŐwoh
nehTÔ .kcab dedlof srae siH
gnileef eht dna ,srae denettalf eht ,seye sih ni truh eht ,saw ti erehT
IÔ .seye sih debbur dna nwod dekool cennef ehT
tahw no pu kcip tŐnac eh fi ,elpmis dna nialp mih llet ot deen I .thgir
Ő.gnihtyna em gnillet tŐnerew uoy dna wonk ot dedeen yllaer tsuj I
dŐwoHÔ .rood eht ot deddon kriK
oGÔ ŐŃerom mih gnitruh sŐti kniht uoy tŐnod tub
fo gnileef eht htiw thgin yadirF nitraM tem eh dna
,tteS ehT   dloG lleyK yb
uoYÔ .dehgual dna dexaler neht ,kcab srae sih yal regdab ehT Ő.orcleVÔ Ő.gnilfitSÔ
sŐtahTÔ .elbat eht deppals ynnoL Ő!yeh
,etal os eb htob ot atroP dna ynnoL rof lausu tŐnsaw ti ekil sgniht gniyas dna dnuora gnikool tpek eltsimocac ehT
,elbat rab a ta desuap trihs nitas knip gniremmihs a ni xof A
.od ylbisualp thgim eltsimocac detraeh-gib eht gnihtemos ekil demees tahT
Ő!uoy htiw ecnahc a sah eh skniht llits eh
,seramthgin sŐkriK fo eno ekil hcum yrev saw sihT
.wodniw moordeb sih dnoyeb ssenkrad eht otni tuo derats kriK
?eb dŐew erehw mih dlot I kniht uoyŃtahW .wonk tŐnod
eeSÔ .pu dellup tsuj dah nades kcalb a erehw ,bruc eht ot deirruh dna meht ot devaw atroP
ti sŐtahWÔ Ő.noitceles reeb dooGÔ Ő?sliatkcoc dooG
,ylteiuq ekops dna naV morf yawa dekool eh hguoht nevE
.ffo rae ruoy etib lliw ereh regdab eht ro tuo hctaw retteB .uoy
,kriK ta derats cennef ehT
Ő.mih gnillet neeb sŐohw eno eht erŐuoy
,rehto hcae ta derats yehT .deppots naV dna
,enog saw xof ehT
.tnemom a rof ecnelis ni tas eerht gniniamer ehT
.oNÔ Ő.semit wef a uoy otni nur ot deneppah eh dna
IÔ Ő.revo sŐti mih llet tsuj dŐuoy
Ő.nuf sdnuos taht
.ereh meht thguorb eh revenehw denialpmoc yllausu sdneirf eerht sih fo eno tub
dŐtahWÔ .srae reh fo ffo tesdaeh eht nekat dah retto ehT
naem IÔ .yltfos dias eh
diDÔ .detniuqs eH Ő.tiaW
evŐIÔ .ffo wap sih koohs nitraM tub ,mih pots ot tuo dehcaer kriK
.dias nitraM Ő,pu em tes
,kool a mih evag ynnoL
Ő.sserdda siht dah ohw eno ylno eht erŐuoy dna ereh sŐeh won dnA
ŐÉtsuj ,yug dab a ton sŐeH .detseretni erŐuoy fi
,meht dnif ot erehw naV gnillet saw ohw eno eht saw nitraM taht mih gnillet saw sŐkriK dna
oSÔ Ő.ti timda ot tnaw tŐnseod tsuj tub sah eh ebyam rO
pu nrut ot naV rof ecalp lausunu tsom eht neeb dah llam eht esuaceb tcepsus pot sih saw ynnoL   ***   ŐŃtŐnsaw
mih no dehgiew ecneserp sŐcennef eht
?erusserPÔ Ő.ti eldnah tŐnac I dna erusserp hcum oot tsuj sŐerehT
,hUÔ Ő.uoy denioj I fi yako eb dŐti dias ynnoLÔ
,ereh tŐnsaw naV fI
Éleef uoy edam I fi ,kriK ,yrrosŃ
esuaceBÔ Ő.mih pleh ot evah tŐnod uoY .ygnilc sŐeh wonk I
:yojne esaelP     .dloGlleyK@ ta
.meht nioj og ot noislupmoc on tlef eH
sknahTÔ .dias eh Ő,tsafkaerb teg
ŐkstÔ a ekil dnuos a edam elbat ybraen a ta xof A
?meht fo owt eht ,rof gnitiaw erew yeht tahw taht saW
uoYÔ Ő.oot siht fo lla dediova evŐdluoc uoy ,ytic eht revo lla mih gniklats fo daetsni saw laed eht tahw tuo talf kriK deksa dna dellac tsuj dŐuoy
tuBÔ Ő.ereht neeb lla evŐeWÔ .dias ynnoL Ő,looc
Ő,epyt ruoy ekil dekool eh thguoht tsuj
Ő.enoyna gnitnorfnoc ton yb detnaw ew tahw tog htob
.seidob gnivom fo retsulc eht otni kcab deraeppasid
erŐyehTÔ .dias nitraM Ő,sserdda gnorw eht meht tnes evŐtsum uoy
skoob sih dna lleyK tuoba noitamrofni eroM
.tŐndah yeht ,hguoht ,thginoT
Ő?eb ot desoppus taht sŐgnol
,retteb tlef taht
,ysub ytterp neeb sŐkriK
inamleZ yelsiap eulb sih fo ralloc eht ta dellup eH
,meht fo lla ot eyb-doog dias dna doots cennef eht os ,oot niaga naV tespu ot demees taht dna
.gnivom eno rehtien
Ő.enif enif yako wo tsuj tŐnac uoy ,em naht reggib erŐuoy esuaceb tsuJ
,kriK htiw yako eb dluow ti fi deksa naV nehT
.ylthgils drawrof dekrep srae sŐnitraM dna
,stnecs fo amsaim eht dekil kriK
?esle erehwemos gnittis eb thgim atroP dna ynnoL kniht uoY
.erraC eL nhoJ fo tuo thgir
.sdneirf rieht ot
Ő!mih htiw rehtegot kcab teg thgim uoy skniht llits
kooLÔ Ő?krow elpoep woh dnatsrednu uoy oD
.kooH deR dna tteS ehT dna Édna
.ereh revo gnimoc erŐyeht os ,skcolb wef a tsuj sŐtI .nesoR no ecalp siht ta revo
.dehgis kriK Ő.thgir lla ,thgir
tahtÔ ,swap egral sih gnidaerps ,dias kriK Ő,eeSÔ Ő.skeew
.dnim reven ,bmud
,nalp txen eht ot no gnivom daeh sih ni ydaerla ,kriK dnA
eHÔ .drawrof gninael ,dias kriK Ő,nwod
.emit emas eht ta dezzub enohp sŐkriK ŐÉyeh hO
,sgnileef sŐelpoep truh ot etah uoy wonk I
,hOÔ Ő?naV ot gniklat saw eh fi nitraM gniksa tsuj fo daetsni esle ecalpemos su dnes yllaer uoy
.ecnedicnioc si eciwt ,ecnatsneppah si ecnO
oNÔ .efil sih ni yllareneg ton fi
IÔ Ő?bulc eht ta ti yalp annog uoY
,detiaw lla atroP dna ,ynnoL ,nitraM
Ő.tfyL ym sŐereht ,yeH .looCÔ Ő.sserdda
.ffuts gnizama emos ni gnignirb erŐuoy dna enil ssab eht evol I
tahWÔ .mih degdun nitraM erofeb gnihtyna fo kniht tŐndluoc eh tub
?ti tuoba od ot gniog uoy era tahW
uoYÔ .enohporcim eht deppop taht dnuos evissucnoc a ,detrons raeb ralop ehT
ylerutamerp mih htiw pu nekorb dah kriK taht nitraM decnivnoc dah naV
eWÔ .knird sih no seye sih tpek eltsimocac ehT Ő.wonk IÔ
.raeppasid dna diuqil knip eht otni evid ot detnaw eh hguoht sa ssalg sih ta nwod derats eH
rof ro ,gnitadommocca gnieb ton rof tluaf sih llits saw ti wohemos taht gnileef eht yawa esahc tŐndluoc eh
,sknahTÔ .redluohs sŐraugaj eht dettap ehS Ő.teg I ,uoY
Ő?won ot desoppo
?trihs inamleZ oraT denrettap neerg emil a nwo ro ,rae eno ni sgnir edirp fo retsulc a evah dluow meht fo ynam woh tub
Ő?og ot su tnaw syug
,seirf sih fo erutarepmet eht ot esion ot stnecs morf gnihtyna tuoba nialpmoc ot tsekciuq yllausu saw nitraM
Ő.uoy fo rehtiEÔ Ő?mih ro
Ő.naV ot letni gnikaens ,ffuts yps gniod osla erŐuoy ,yawynA
IÔ Ő?yag sŐeh wonk neve uoy od woh
Ő,ti eveileb yllaer tŐndid
?llaM retsehC ehT ?llam eht ot tnew syug uoY
Ő.gniht eht
,srab tnereffid owt ta erew yeht taht tcaf eht tuo gnitros saw nitraM elihW
Ő.ylkciuq taht llam eht ot nettog evah
Ő.eromyna gniog erŐew erehw mih llet tŐnow I ,yrros mŐI
.moor ecnad eht otni kcab derats dna
,mih ta detcerid neeb evah thgim taht
,eivom a hctaw dna emoh tis ot derreferp eh taht dias dah kriK nehw neve ,semit wef a ecnad ot mih deggard dah naV
,kriK .dnuora gnimoc pots ot mih lleT
Ő?yeht eraŃsu htiw tis mih evah ot gniog ton
,naorg sŐynnoL gnirongi
.gnidnatsrednusim a lla si siht wonk
,rehtegot kcab su teg ot gniyrt erew uoy ebyam thguoht
,meht no gniyps saw xe siH
uoYÔ .senecs dna stnemugra rof
,kcab tnew srae sih dna
Ő.ti tuoba suoicarg eb os ,ti did eh tub ,siht od ot gnol oot yaw mih koot tI
Ő?niagAÔ Ő?niaga gniht elohw siht hguorht og ot evah I
.emit erom eno moor eht dennacs kriK
Ő?taht no pu dekcip tŐnsah eh kniht uoY !skeew eerht rof mih gniees neeb tŐnevah
ehTÔ Ő?tekcaj ecin eht ni eno eht ,regdab taht tuoba
emac ti nehw kcehc eht debbarg eh litnu
,deksa dŐeh noitseuq eht rewsna ot nitraM rof gnitiaw
tuoba ,esle enoemos tuoba klat uoy raeh dŐeh ebyam thguoht I dna
.ecnedicnioc sŐti
,erew atroP dna ynnoL erehw rab rehto eht ta revo saw eh ebyam neht
erŐuoYÔ .pu dekool nitraM
.raehrevo dluow naV ,gniht eno roF
tIÔ Ő.ot naem tŐndid I
IÔ .daeh sih koohs eltsimocac ehT
taht denrael IÔ .delims kriK
nehTÔ Ő.rab a ni yug a teem ot tnaw tŐnod
,dias eh gnihtyreve raeh dluow naV esuaceb ti tuoba gnihtyna yas tŐndluoc kriK dna
.ereht cisum eht ot gnivom seidob eht dna
.looCÔ .delims eltsimocac ehT Ő.eruSÔ Ő?neve
,aiMÔ .wodniw eht ta niaga decnalg dna
,tcejbus eht egnahc ot yaw emos fo kniht ot deirt eH
.moor eht fo kcab eht ni rab eht ta gnittis cennef eht deciton dna pu dekool kriK
.dlrow eht ni tsom dekil eh elpoep eht fo tnorf ni sekatsim tsap sih fo lla ni thguac
owTÔ .yllufelab raugaj eht deye nitraM
.eltsimocac eht ot denrut kriK
uoYÔ Ő?tuo gnidnif eh si woh os ,gnihtyna ro rettiwT no gniog erŐew secalp eht tuoba gniklat ton mŐI dna pu ekorb ew ecnis skeew owt eht ni semit eerht pu nwohs sah naV ,si tniop
.taht ot timmoc neve tŐnac uoy tuB .setad rehto no gniog
Ő.neht ,meht llet tŐnow
rab eht ot revo ynnoL dewollof ehS
.rood eht hguorht deklaw cennef eht ,tnemom taht tA
sŐtahTÔ Ő?tsurt uoy tŐnod ohW
,tnaruatser eht dennacs naV ,ylwolS
.nitraM dna kriK ot txen staes eht koot atroP dna eh elihw naV rof dnuora ti gnuws dna
sŐtahTÔ .neercs eht ta derats regdab ehT
IÔ Ő?ereh erew ew wonk eh
?dnuora gnikool peek uoy od yhw
,syuGÔ .eltsimocac ot regdab morf dekool naV Ő?tahw em
.looc ton sŐtahT .uoy gniklats rof yrros mŐI
,metsys noitalitnev detauqitna eht demlehwrevo dworc tsedom a neve tub ,sthgin yadsruhT no lluf yletelpmoc tog reven
,tas eh regnol ehT
elpuoCÔ .elpmet sih otni gnisserp swalc tnulb sih
sŐtahTÔ .daeh sih ni nalp a gnimrof ydaerla
.gnilfitSÔ ŐŃsaw yug taht ,naem I .thgil
nrevat tnemesab egral a
eson evitisnes sŐeltsimocac eht thginot tub
:ynnoL morf egassem eht ta dekool htob yehT
llAÔ Ő.mih llac tsael ta rO .nosrep ni ti oD
IÔ ,gniraeh sŐnaV fo tuo dna rood eht tuo deklaw yeht sa yllausac dias
Ő.tsap eht fo trap ,ekil ,sŐtIÔ .dedda atroP
.taht eb ot ton tuo denrut ti fi enoemos esucca ot tnaw tŐndid tsuj I .pu lla ti gnittes ,nuf fo dnikŃsaw
.sŐkriK ni wap sih detser naV
,nitraM ot erats sih detfihs dah kriK Ő?tahW
.noitasrevnoc yreve fo dnuorgkcab eht derocs tsetorp fo enihw tnatsnoc esohw
,dloG lleyK yb ÓenozdneirF tnegAŇ
Ő?huh ,sdahalaG ehTÔ .atroP ot denrut regdab ehT Ő.oSÔ
Ő.ni deklaw tsuj
,eivom dnoB tsetal eht tuoba deklat yeht ,noitasrevnoc taht detcelfed kriK nehw dna
oSÔ .elbat eht no gnippat-pat swalc sih
Ő?rehtegot gnitteg lla erŐuoy erehw naV gnillet si sdneirf ruo fo eno kniht
tIÔ .mih fo tuo tsrub sdrow ehT Ő!yrros
,hAÔ .rood eht tuo kcab thgir deklaw dna denrut eh neht dna
ÉhAÔ .deksa ynnoL Ő?dellac
,eltsimocac eht tcartsid ot yaw emos rof dehcraes dna
.em depmud nivlaK nehw semit fo hcnub a syug uoy dehctid
.tset a saw taht ,yeH
;ypsretnuoc eht saw eH
.emit siht pu gniwohs rehtob ot ton naV llet erus rof dŐeh ,yps eht erew eh fi tub
edis eht ot kcab srae sih dekcilf kriK Ő.ah
,dezzub enohp sih emit yrevE
Ő.duol tuo gniyrc rof ,llam gnikaerf eht ta saw ti taht erofeb syad owt dnA
ŐŃtub ,gnihtemos ro ,pu gnuh erew I fi esnes ekam dluow
.kcab gnitxet saw nitraM ,mih pots dluoc kriK erofeB
,naV saw ti ,hguone erus dna
gnikaepSÔ .thgim ti thguoht dŐeh sa hcum sa kriK tespu tŐndid
.revo sŐti mih llet og ot sllab eht evah tŐnod uoy
.oNÔ Ő?dnoB semaJ erew uoy kniht uoy
.nac uoy ,esiurc og ot tnaw syug uoy
.noinapmoc roop a saw
,azziP kooH deR rof tes saw ti keew siht dna
IÔ .oot meht ot eyb-doog yas ot tuo yaw sih no redluohs eht no atroP gnippat
,uoy ot deil I dna ,em ot deil uoy
,teercsid eb dna su hctaw emoc ot mih dlot I oS
erŐeWÔ .wap eerf sih htiw meht neewteb devaw eH ŐÉos
ŐÉknup-tla ot no evom ew erofeb tub ,ksa ot tnaw tŐndid
ehTÔ .yas ot mih rof gnitiaw erew yeht tahw wenk eh dna
Ő,su no gniyps si xe ypeerc ym ,yeHÔ ,ekil gnihtemos ,ot detnaw eh tahw dias eh fi dna
,sdrow eht dias eh sa nevE
neht dna regnol tnemom a delggurts elims evarb sŐnitraM
,thguoht kriK ,on hO
.uoy gnitad peek tŐnac I tub ,yug ecin a erŐuoy
?rehtegot kcab naV dna mih teg ot tpmetta ysmulc a saw emussa ylno dluoc kriK tahw rof elbisnopser eb eltsimocac eht dluow yhw oS
woHÔ .atroP ot denrut ynnoL
?erew ew erehw rednow uoy tŐndid ,kriK ,yeh
,wol eciov sih tpek kriK
Ő.on no teb annog
tŐndluoc eH .naV was I erofeb setunim evif ekil saw taht yawyna dna ,morf saw ti erehw ton tub erutcip trihs a detsop ynnoL
,gnilleTÔ .niaga kriK decaf eh sa elims tneconni ,evarb a no tup ot deirt eh hguoht
eMÔ .deksa nitraM
IÔ .taorht sih deraelc naV
,neercs eht ta derats kriK
eWÔ .kriK detsaot dna ssalg sih detfil nitraM Ő.haey ,yeHÔ Ő.skrow
,tnemtnioppasid sŐnaV htiw laed ot evah ot gniog saw eH
Ő,yllacinhceTÔ Ő?noitasrevnoc drawrofthgiarts a evah tsuj ew nac ,ylsuoires
ebyaMÔ .gninetsilg eson kcalb reh ees dluoc eh taht hguone esolc ni denael aiM
teiuQÔ .srae dna sdaeh rieht denrut meht dnuora elpoeP
naVÔ Ő?tahW ?ohw ,ha
moor eht ssorca yawflah noitasrevnoc a ot netsil ot gniyrt cennef a hcihw
Ó.tuo ti erugiFŇ .doG ym
;snalp eht gnikam seno eht yllareneg tŐnerew skoob eht ni seips retsam ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
Ő?ohWÔ Ő?nossel a denrael evŐuoy taht ksa ot hcum oot
rab denepo-ylwen a fo sserdda eht nitraM tnes kriK ,yadsruhT
.rehto hcae ta dekool retto dna raugaj ehT
,yrgna erŐuoy dna derit erŐuoy dna thgin sŐti
.enoyreve htiw tuo gnignah pots tsuj tŐnac uoY
.ti ekil dŐuoy ,ynnoL
?ni klaw ot ruoh na flah gnitiaw neht dna em gniwollof naV sI .em llet oS
Ő.kcehc em teL .tegrof I ,wonk uoy
llŐIÔ .htaerb a koot eH ŐÉsnaem Óysub mŐIŇ
.yawa selbat wef a morf
flesmih deleets kriK
Ő?meht fo eno taht
sihtÔ ,gnihtemos tuoba gnikniht saw eh nehw did eh ekil swap sih otni liat sih gnillup ,deksa nitraM
ehTÔ Ő.strihs erom uoy teg mih tel dluohs uoy neht ,si ti fI
,trats dluow srehto eht fo eno depoh kriK
.noisivelet eht ta pu dekrep srae rieht tpek yldetniop yeht erehw
.edud ,lla ta ti hguorht enog tŐnevah uoy si tniop elohw ehTÔ .dehgual nitraM
uoYÔ .kriK ot dias nitraM Ő,si gniht
,tteS ehT ni sexof cennef fo rebmun yna neeb evah dluoc ereht ,esruoc fO
dnAÔ .elbat eht deppat dna
?syug uoy era erehW
ecnarelot laminim sŐkriK pu dellif dah eciwt Őog ti telÔ ot nitraM gnillet dna
,mih htiw seiradnuob ssucsid dluoc ohw enoemos dedeen naV taht denialpmoc kriK nehw rae citehtapmys a tneb dah nitraM
rab ybraen a fo sserdda eht atroP dna ynnoL tnes neht dna
.ecalp tnereffid a enoyreve llet tub
tIÔ .lwocs a htiw ssalg sih debbarg kriK
,no og ot gnidnetni ,nitraM ot kcab denrut eH
Ő.ecivda eht rof
,dloG lleyK yb ÓenozdneirF tnegAŇ saw sihT
Ńeht saw atroP dna
tlAÔ .seye reh dellor atroP Ő.knup weNÔ
mŐIÔ .regna otni desaerc
,ereht tŐnsaw ohw dneirf rehtona rof gnikool saw eh ekil
.od reve tŐndluow
,enif eb dluow ti dias kriK dna
eno ylno eht
,tnasaelp dna mraw ,tcatnoc ehT
gnignirb yeht era yhWÔ .naV tnatculer ylbisiv a ot gniklat
.sdneirf sih fo emos ot gniyl tuoba ytliug ssel tib a leef mih edam dna
sŐtIÔ .daeh sih koohs nitraM