,eerf ylurt elggurts ot tseb syawla
denoissimmoc eb yam dna
”eciravA & alocirgA“   yojne
gniyap rof mraf sih lles dluow reed eht ,os dnA ,deed dna drow ni hturt detartsnomed yehT
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR  .noos
,relevart wollef ruoy
,emulP eht morF ,yrteop fo noitcelloc tsrif sih hsilbup-fles ot si laog siH .moc.liamg@snikleivim
.ytirepsorp ot delkcahs dna dnuob nahT“
.liamg@snikleivim ta liame aiv ro
,edaced a revo rof yrteop fo tfarc sih detcefrep sah ohw
”!deen ruoy yfsitas lliw eseht morf htlaew hcuS“
esaelP  daD regdaB yldduC eht
siT‘“ gniylper ,hturt a etats ot xof eht desuac tI
gniyalpsid sevlow tnahcrem yb detisiv saW
ees ot emoh sih otni yaw reh edam dnA
,tnuocca ytiniffAruF sih no seton aiv yrteop sih rof
.eb ot saw ti tsaef reh noos taht ,neh ehT
;gniyal dedlig sti - neh siht - ezirp tsenif ruO“
,xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb ”eciravA & alocirgA“ saw sihT     ”.ytirepsorp
xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM  yb meop a
.eelf did htlaew dna htlaeh fo epoh sih lla ereH
;eelg deniur taht seirc ot denruter reed ehT
.deerg ot debmuccus tsaf eh ,ecnegilid nI gniyats fo daetsni dna ,erusaert ysae fO
floWcaM boR si sihT
,dees gniwos morf tser ta ,reed gnimraf A
gniyrp saw feiht nexiv a thgin ta neht tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,gniyd won neh eht nopu gnarps ehs sa oS
,xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb