"?meht fo yna thguob ohw rebmemer uoy oD"
.deksa sicnarF "?meht ees I yaM"
.egap eht no yltcerid enihs thgilnus eht gnittel
",kcab shtnom eerhT"
.tam eht no deppots ohw einrE saw tI
.kcen sih dnuora nekot eht reh dewohs yaJ .deksa ehs
.dedda einrE ",erom spahrep
taht" ,niaga teerts eht no tuo erew yeht nehw dias sicnarF ",oS"
,rehto eno tsael ta saw ereht yltnerappa dnA" .dias sicnarF
.tib a kcab srae sih gnidlof
.nekot sih ni eloh eht hguorht dne eno dedaerht ylluferac neht ,eerf
detnuoc yaJ "?meht teg uoy did oga gnol woH
".flesmih rof em demialc tsuj sicnarF"
".ot ti tnaw htob ew kniht I tuB" .dias sicnarF ",skrow yllaer ti fi ees ot gniog tsuj er'eW"
"'!hguonE' seirc tsrif ohw mih ekat lived eht dna
.eulav detimil fo si ecnedive eht taht ezilaer dna
.decniw flow eht ,ylmulg gniddoN
.yltfos yrev dias eh ",ysaE"
".oga sraey deid ohw elpoep ot gnoleb tsum seman eseht llA
",ereh revO" .deksa eh
,did uoy sa eman eht eviver ot deirt esle enoyna fi"
".su ta hgual lliw niW" .deerga yaJ
"?oga raey a tsuj ngis ot noissessop s'enoemos ni saw ti fi
"?hctaw eht ot revo siht nrut tsuj ew t'ndluohS" .dias
"?kcab ti nrae I nac woH
.sicnarF ,nwo ruoy no tuo ti krow ot uoy detcepxe reven I" .elzzum sih dnuora wap sih gnipparw fo erutseg detareggaxe na htiw ,demialcxe
.ti no srettel eerht esoht htiw dah ew esle gnihtyna rof gniksa"
.gnihton seifingis tI" .deralced sicnarF ",enoyreve dna gnihtyreve ta shgual niW"
.wap sih dereffo einrE
,decnuonna einrE ",ylirassecen toN"
,sselgninaem s'ti tuB" .dias eh
einrE" .deddon sicnarF .deksa eh "?ydnarB"
?ti ni s'tahW" .derednow
,yltcerid yaJ gnisserdda ,dias ehs
"'.F' na ni sdne dna trohs si emanrus ehT
,nwo rieht no ffo enog dna evael rieht nekat dah dneirflrig sih dna niW dna
.sicnarF ta neht ,yaJ ta tsrif gnikool tpek einrE
".yllaer ,htob uoy rof dalg m'I
ti tib dna ffo htgnel a derusaem eH
".ti ni nettirw seman eht lla htiw
,desoppus sicnarF
,rood dne tsae eht hguorht mrod eht deretne yehT
",eerht lla rof stnuocca tahT"
,neht thguob uoy eno eht
",retteb dah ew kniht I"
.yaJ dias ",taht rewsna nac I" .deksa einrE
.denepo rood eht ,erofeb rehto hcae nees reven d'yeht fi sa
",ruof ebyam ro ,egdirb eht morf steerts eerhT"
".YC164 ,flesmih yb"
,spil sih delkcit eugnot s'yaJ .htaerb gnirahs
.tenretni eht no sa llew sa tamrof tnirp ni dehsilbup seirots sah dna
.niaga swap sih ni elzzum sih gnidih
,ffur kcen sih otni delttes ti taht os srae dna elzzum sih revo pool eht dekrow dna
.revir eht no nwod seirotimrod nredom eht fo eno ni devil yaJ ,deneppah ti sA
.repap eussit fo tekcap elttil a otni sniahc eht parw ot dedeecorp dna
",erots euqitna na ni pu dekcip I knuj fo eceip a
,rethgil gniworg traeh sih tlef ydaerla sicnarF
dnuorg eht no gniyl dnuof saw"
mih ot eulav on fo saw tub ,ylimaf sih ni nwod dessap neeb dah ti demialc eH
.sretrauq gnivil s'yaJ rof ffo tes yeht dnA .deerga sicnarF
.egap eht no erutangis tsal eht ot gnitniop
.rehtegot swap sih gnippalc ,deerga yaJ ",thgir er'uoY"
",yaJ ,oN" .detsetorp yaJ
.743 ni kcab ohR atE ahplA ot sevlesmeht degdelp ohw srehto spahrep dna stneduts fo serutangis eht sah tI" .derewsna yaJ
,dias einrE ",esuaceB"
.scsid eht dah I retfa pu ti dekool ylno I"
,gnidliub raey driht a ni saw moor ehT
.wap sih dettap sicnarF tub ,elbat eht rednu edih dna nwod knirhs dluoc eh dehsiw eh ekil dekool yaJ ".drow
"?thgin tsal redrum taht htiw detaicossa era syug uoY
",nekot ruoy em wohs ,niW"
.pohs thgir eht saw ti taht meht derussa yaJ tub ,ecalp eht dnuof yeht erofeb snoitcerid rof tuoba gniksa emos koot dna
,derewsna yaJ .deksa einrE
".devrats m'I ?hcnul tuoba woh woN"
"?regdel siht si erehw oS" .daeh sih koohs einrE
,egdelp eht dengis dah raekcalB niW dna sicnarF hcihw no eno eht kcab gninruT
",ti deppord egelloc eht eht taht raey eht dnoyeb deunitnoc puorg eht taht wonk ew tsael ta ,lleW"
.oga syad wef a kcirt emas eht gniyalp derebmemer eh sa seye sih otni emac gnidnatsrednu neht dna deknilb yaJ
.deksa eh "?yaJ ,gniyduts uoy era tahW"
.yllaer ,noitamrofni fo tol a t'nsi erehT
"?yhW" .derewsna yaJ
.hcnul deredro dna ,lrig sih dna niW ot txen elbat eht ta nwod tas yehT
ksed eht ta nwod tas eH
.dah ew tsal eht erew eerht esoht diarfa m'I ,ris ,oN"
egdirb eht dessorc yehT
.srae ruoy revo hcaer nac I os deb eht no tis"
einrE "?dlo os erew taht erofeb serutangis eht lla erus uoy erA"
"?ecalp eht si erehW" .deddon
smra yrruf ,gnorts ni dedlofne flesmih tlef nooccar ehT ".yaJ ,em ssiK"
.evol tsrif ym neeb syawla sah ti tub
syellup dna sepor rieht htiw og ot desu srekrow egrab eht erehw gniklaw
,743 ni egelloc eht yb dezingocer saw tI
.sevlehs eht revo decnalg nooccar ehT
.nottahC ni worromoT s'yadretseY dellac pohs a ta meht fo eerht thguob I"
.reh dlot eh ",oga shtnom wef a ereh eseht fo eerht thguob I"
.rellik eht dnif pleh lliw siht fi sa kool t'nseod ti tuB" .dias sicnarF
.ylesolc erom kool ot tneb eh dna
.reilrae mih nees dah sicnarF ecnis tahwemos pu derebos evah ot deraeppa ohw ,niW ot txen
doots yaJ .snooccar owt eht htiw tis ot revo einrE dna yaJ del eh os
,daeh sih koohs flow eht ",oN"
.ylsuoiruc dehctaw yaJ
.ydaerla uoy dekil I esuaceb dalg saw I
.deddon yaJ dna sicnarF htoB
.wap sih tuo dleh sicnarF ".nekot
,motsuc ruoy rof uoy knahT"
".ees I ,raebsekahS ekil uoY"
.eye sih ni feihcsim fo tnilg a htiw dias sicnarF ",yaJ ,won skeew fo elpuoc a rof enoemos htiw ffo em hctam ot gniyrt neeb sah einrE"
nottahC ni erehwemos srehto lareves era ereht taht su dlot ti"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.deerga einrE ",trats doog a s'tahT"
.253 ni erew setad esoht llA
.htob deirt I" ,dennirg einrE ",yllautcA"
.pohs eht tfel yeht sa dias
,sruo fo dneirf A" .dehgual yaJ .wonk ot detnaw yletaidemmi einrE "?niW s'ohW ?niW" .mih dlot sicnarF
,sehcnul eerht lla rof gniyap no tsisni did yaJ ".tniop siht ta
".segap tnecer erom eht fo eno no
.nekot ruoy em wohs ,woN
nozamA no dna ",ovitlA"
.eno hcae kcehc t'ndid I" .deksa
,tnadnep ro tekcol a rof sa ,sniahc kcen erew yehT
"?meht fo erom yna evah uoy oD"
",thgir er'uoy sseug I"
,esruoc fo lausu sa yawa dehcnum einrE
?gninioj erew uoy em dlot uoy eno tahT"
.derewsna yaJ ",noitseuq dooG"
,ereht teg ot htapwot dlo eht koot dna
.od sdisru dna sdinac ylno sa ssik dluoc yeht os ylthgils daeh sih gninrut ylevitcnitsni
".emit eht ta ti fo esle gnihtyna kniht t'ndid I
sdoog lanosrep fo reward sih ot thgiarts tnew sicnarF ,moor eht edisni erew yeht ecno dna
",pohs s'relaed euqitna na otni tog yeht woh snialpxe hcihw
".gnihtyna tpurretni ot naem t'ndid I" ,dias eh ",yrroS"
.kcab sih dniheb ti dleh eh nehT
".ytlucaf ro tneduts ,detsil flU oN"
,emirc eht fo enecs eht ta eseht fo eno deppord evah dluow enoemos taht ecnedicnioc ynnuf a si erus ti tub ,meht evig ot noitamrofni lufesu yna evah t'nod eW"
,dedne ti sdnoces wef a nI
llaH supuL drawot kcab ylksirb dehcram eH
,derewsna ehs ",ylniatreC"
einrE ",tneduts a neve t'nsaw yug siht spahrep oS"
,gnihtemos tuoba gnikniht ,ecaps otni ffo gnitfird tpek yaJ
.egac a ni roolf driht eht ot meht koot taht tfil ytivarg nredom a saw ereht dna
,orevO ovitlA yb osla ,”srettilG tahT llA“ htiw
einrE ",htuom ym tuhs lleW" .deralced eh
,rewsna t'ndid sicnarF .deksa yaJ
eht ",pihsnamnep elbirret sah eh ,si eh reveohW"
,oot koob taht dengis rellik lautca eht taht elbissop tsael ta s'ti oS"
.deksa sicnarF "?esac eht evlos pleh ot od ew nac tahw oS"
.mih desaeler yaJ sa
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,orevO ovitlA yb ,”srettilG tahT llA“ saw sihT
.meht erofeb elbat eht no yal llits hcnul laitnatsbus a fo sniamer ehT
.delims dna nwo sih ni wap s'nooccar eht koot flow ehT .dias eh
.relaed euqitna eht rof dedaeh yeht ,taht fo erac nekat dah yeht nehw dna
".erom yna meht edih ot deen on s'ereht ,su tub enoyna ot gnihton naem yeht ecniS" .dias eh
.daeh reh koohs tibbar ehT
.ydnarb fo elttob ynit eht tuo dellup dna
,ytpme saw meht ot txen elbat ehT
.snekot ro segdab ralimis evah ohw
".kcub roop taht fo ydob eht raen
.dehgual sicnarF ",einrE ,yeH"
.wodniw eht rednu ksed gnitirw a dna
,regdel dnuob rehtael taht saw dah ew llA
".taert yM" .dias yaJ ",etarbelec ot s'ybuR ot og s'teL"
",einrE ,bulc yranigami yletelpmoc a fo melbme ehT"
.tib a deppalf srae reh os daeh reh gnikahs ,dias lrig eht
ti sah romur tuB .ti htiw od ot gnihton dah ew ,einrE ,oN"
,nemeltneg ,emocleW"
wodniw eht morf thgilnus eht ni detnilg tI
.demialcxe eh "!flU"
.deerga yaJ ",thgir er'uoY"
.liart sih ni gniwollof nosyerG yaJ htiw
,lleW" .derewsna yaJ
.deddon sicnarF .ti tuhs eh nehT
,demialcxe yaJ "!sdoG" .dias eh
,htuom sih denepo eh dna
".meht fo riap eht rof sreppoc owT
.delims sicnarF dna
.on ,ris ,eman yb toN" .deksa sicnarF
.slaitini gnidda ssentiw a htiw
.ylbaborp ,tnadnecsed ro evitaler A"
,deerga tibbar eht ",ris ,doog yreV"
,ti eviecer ot yppah saw I
.rof doots ti thguoht I tahw fo esuaceb tsuj ton dna
"?taht tuoba od ot gniog ew era tahW
?kniht uoy t'nod ,repeekpohs eht ksa og si od ot gniht tsrif eht ekil smees ti ,lleW"
.ti evah uoy" ,dias eh ",t'nac I"
.moor 'sicnarF dna s'einrE ot tsesolc eht ,yltneinevnoc
.tnatsiser ylhgih si ereh sicnarF tuB
.eson sih dnuora elbaeciton saw ti os hguone gnihsulb ,dias eh
.morf emac htruof eht erehw wonk t'nod I
.gnidnib eht rof tpecxe
.gnihtyna ot tpada ot ydaer saw eH
.segap eht denimaxe dna
.ti dias eh sa neve daeh sih gnikahs
,ffuWcM ,no dael" ,deerga einrE
,os ro etunim a retfA
.s'ybuR ot ffo dehcram lla yeht oS ".nemeltneg
".did uoy sa tsuj koob emas eht desu evah thgim eh
.yletaidemmi dezingocer sicnarF taht emulov dnuob rehtael a tuo gnillup dna
.delbmum eh ",gnitirwdnah dab gnidaer htiw ecitcarp emos evah I"
.flesmih ot elims sicnarF gnikam
".eerht eht ylno dah yeht
.worbeye na gnisiar ,deksa yaJ "?slriG"
.drow eht fo esnes lausu eht ni ton tsael ta rO .laer t'nsaw tI
.xob denil tevlev a ni sniahc enif emos ot gnitniop
.niaga uoy ot esolc gnitteg rof esucxe nettor a tahW
,egdirb eht morf steerts evif yllautca saw tI
,tem selzzum rieht dna
.thguoht sicnarF ,hcum oot gniknird neeb dah eh spahreP
"?od ew nac esle tahw ,lleW"
.taht did I eveileb t'nac I"
.mih derewsna lrig eht ",lla ta ton ,hO"
.niaga redrum eht pu thguorb sicnarF
,tib a deggaw liat siH ".evol
.delims eh ",esiwekiL"
.em htiw od ot erom gnihton evah dluohs uoY" .dias eh
.meht ni tseretni na dewohs nameltneg siht nehw desirprus t'nsaw I os ,sevlow erew sreyub eht lla kniht I tuB
"?yeht era tahW .eno evah hcae uoy taht ees I" ,dias eh ",KO"
.pot eht delaes dah taht xaw tfos eht ot kcuts saw nekot PHA eht
einrE ",ssim ,pleh ruoy rof uoy knahT"
,tekcop renni sih otni ti tup dna lecrap eht koot sicnarF
.potretnuoc eht no sreppoc owt dial dna
,nwod wols ot detrats enoyreve nehW
,ytiniffA ruF no mih dnif nac uoY
",elbirret yllaer m'I"
",rae ym ni dehcnup uoy eloh eht gnisnaelc rof ti detseggus
.yltnelis
.nemeltneg ,yaw sihT" .rood eht denepo eH ".einrE
.daeh sih koohs sicnarF
"?uoy pleh ew nac woh
einrE ",denoitnem uoy koob regdel sihT"
,detcepxe dah eh sa tsuj dna ,wap sih ni revo ti denrut eH
nettirw dah rengis eht ti rednu dna dengis saw
”.gninaW nooM suobbiG“
.thgir saw eh dna
,sevlehs no skoob ynam dah yaJ taht dnif ot desaelp saw sicnarF
.ecaf sih revoc ot fi sa edam dna
,tibbar eht fo tnorf ni esac ssalg eht ni gnihtemos no eye sih dah sicnarF
.htaerb peed a koot yaJ ".tnatsiser
,dengis nehw detad erew evoba seman ehT
,puorg lanigiro eht
pohs taht ni pu dne koob eht did woh tuB"
.ylper elgnis eht saw ",dooG"
".sicnarF neht dna ,ngis ot niW tog I nehw egap wen a detrats I
".ti did hcum yrev pleh t'ndid
,hguoht ,egap eht no tsal ehT
,deksa sicnarF "?yrotsih ydahs a htiw noitazinagro daed gnol a sa gnidareuqsam saw eh yhw nialpxe ot yaJ evael dnA"
thgilnus eht ni rehto hcae ta gnikool tsuj
.thgir er'uoy dnA"
",emit emos ta tew neeb dah koob eht spahrep thguoht I .daer ot tluciffid dna yraems erew yehT
.ssarb ylno era yehT"
",erehT".kcen sih dnuora dna daeh s'yaJ revo ecalkcen desivorpmi eht deppils sicnarF dna ,mih deyebo yaJ
tekcop a ni dehsif neht
.ni gud enoyreve elihw esuap a saw ereht dna
.ti ni gnir a tup ot nalp od I
,”srettilG tahT llA“   :yojne esaelP
.253 ni detad saw eno suoiverp eht taht dnuof yeht
.643 dnuora emitemos puorg eht dednuof flU
?neht rof gnitiaw ew era tahw
",gnitivni os ti ekam uoy ecnis ,lleW"
.dneirf sih dettap nooccar ehT ".sicnarF
"?morf emoc sruoy did erehw dnA"
,dettimda sicnarF ",eno eht s'tahT" "?laer ton s'tI
.gnirts fo llab a htiw pu emac eh litnu reward eht ni dehsif eh dna
,nekot sih dah eh fi taht ssenerawa eht htiw
,meht dlot einrE ",yrartnoc eht nO"
,ereht ton saw einrE
htiw detaicossa eb thgim yllaer snekot eht oS" ".843 yb flesti demaner ro dednabsid ydaerla dah puorg eht esle ro dellecnac saw noitingocer taht tub
,dias eh ",sniahc dlog esehT"
,yrots s’yadretsey gniunitnoc er’ew dna
.htuom sih ot wap a tup dna deknilb sicnarF
.swap sih htiw seye sih derevoc dna
.yaJ drawot pu ecaf sih gninrut dna seye sih gnisolc
.detseggus sicnarF ",tser eht dlos ydaerla dah tub ,erom dah yeht spahreP"
.ksed sih fo tekcop eht morf yrotcerid egelloc a dellup yaJ ".ylbaborp
",einrE ,elihw a rof gniyrt pots nac uoY"
.daeh sih koohs eh ,segap reporp eht ot gnippilF
.derewsna ehs ",taht fo erus etiuq m'I ,ris oN"
.gnicaf htuos a htiw ,tnorfretaw eht morf esir elttil a pu
.yllacidohtem dna ylwols tae did eh tub
.sunavlyS ro navlyS si eman tsrif eht erus etiuq m'I" ,dedda eh
.os did eh sa yaJ ta gnikniw
.orevO ovitlA yb
.htaerb sih hctac ot dnoces rehtona koot sicnarF
,skcirb eht revo gniworg saw yvI
,lliswodniw eht ot koob eht deirrac eH .detsisni yaJ
,ereht doots yeht sA ".gnihton
.meht no srettel keerG htiw smeti gnihctam eerht teg ot dalg tsuj saw I
.wap reh ssorca depard meht detneserp dna sniahc eht delgnatnu ehS
.sicnarF ,yrros yllaer ,yllaer m'I
.taorht sih fo wolloh eht ni gnah ot nekot eht gniwolla
.denialpxe sicnarF
",niaga ti esol t'nac I erus gnikam m'I"
,flow rellat eht gnicaf doots dna ,dekniw sicnarF
",dlog yllaer t'nera esoht ,ris ,hO" "?hcum woH"
ksed eht rednu tnemtrapmoc eht otni gnihcaer ,derewsna yaJ
"?uoy t'ndid ,esoprup no rae tfel eht dekcip uoY
.csid ssarb elttil eht decudorp dna
".sowt dna seno yb ffo dlos neeb lla dah srehto eht tub ,yllanigiro meht fo nezod a tuoba erew erehT
einrE ",neht ,gnol os toN" .dias eh
deknilb flow ehT
.einrE ,etaicerppa ylbaborp lliw uoy romuh fo esnes esohw
.dah reve I lla erew eerhT" .dias yaJ
.em ot ti evag uoY
.sselhtrow ton s'tI"
.nosaer emos rof ytilaer morf detcennocsid rehtar demees yaJ
.tuo dnif og s'teL
.htuom sih denepo dna ,deknilb einrE
sa onimA yrruF dna ,lysaeW
,deksa sicnarF "?emit eht ta flU nafetS dna ohR atE ahplA tuoba wonk t'ndid uoy oS"
",ris ,niaga kcab emac flesruoy uoy esruoc fo dnA"
.etarepooc t'ndid dniw ro tnerruc eht nehw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
".yrteop eht nevE" .derewsna yaJ ",ti timda I ,seY"
,wonk I sa raf sA
,txen neppah dluow tahw hcnuh a dah sicnarF
,dias sicnarF ",meht ekat ll'I"
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.s'ybuR ta erew daeH s'floW ehT morf lrig eht dna raekcalB niW
,saw flU nafetS sa elbirret sa er'uoy nehw taht tuoba yrrow ll'I" .elkcuhc sicnarF edam tahT ".em
,yaJ .nosyerG yaJ teem ot uoy tnaw I"
.thgin suoiverp eht redrum eht fo etis eht ta ti tsol evah t'ndluoc ylsuoivbo eh neht
rettam yldrah setunim wef A" .mih dlot sicnarF ",einrE ,hcnul ruoy hsiniF"
",niW ekil tsuj dnuos uoy ,einrE ,sdoG"
.kcirt ykaens a saw ti taht thgir er'uoy ,yaJ ,wonk uoY"
".lwarcs siht fo gnihtyna ekam t'nac I" .yltalf detats nooccar
.gniraew era ew melbme siht htiw detaicossa gnihtemos ro enoemos rof gnikool hctaw eht evah ew" ,dias eh ",oS"
.rae reh dehctarcs tibbar ehT ".meht
.won dessap htob ev'ew kniht I dna"
.dias eh ",erofeb ton dna
,dna egdirb eht ot tsesolc eht saw taht ecnis
",moor ym ni ti evah I" "?ti si erehW
,noitapucco hsiflow a yltcaxe toN" .dettimda eh
,potksed eht no nepo ti daerps yehT
,yllautneve taht nrael lliw hctaw ehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yletaidemmi evael ot ydaer saw einrE ".tuo
.meht teerg ot kcab eht morf emac tibbar a dna
",kniht I ,hctam nwo ym edam ev'I"
.devil yaJ erehw yltcaxe tuo dnif won dluow eh taht thguoht eht ta
,neht mih tih aedi nA
.kcab eht ni spsalc gnirps elttil htiw
.orevO ovitlA rednu
"?kool og ew llahS" .dias
einrE ",thguoht ym ylesicerP"
.won dnim t'nod I yllautca tuB
,morf cisum sekam dna ,sward ,setirw ohw esroh ecnassianeR a
flesmih ot delims sicnarF
",yaJ ,uoy teem ot desaelP"
,dednammoc eh ",nosyerG .rM ,KO"
.taht tnaw did I ,thguoht eh ,seY
.denialpxe yaJ ",sicnarF ,dengis uoy koob egdelp ehT"
,dias yaJ ",doog yreV"
",kniht em tel dna hsuH" .derednow yaJ
.erutangis eht ta ylesolc gnikool saw sicnarF ".gnidnib
",siht ekil melbme na taht
".seyekraD einrE ,etam moor ym si siht
".eno dah ohw sevlesruo naht rehto enoyna fo wonk t'nod ew tey dna
,deunitnoc eh ",tset a fo tros a saw tI"
.dias nooccar eht
",sicnarF ,kool a evah em teL"
.ksa yllaer t'ndid I .elbissop s'tahT"
?tuoba gniklat uoy era tahW" .dias einrE ",tiaW"
.rewsna 'sicnarF saw
",nekot ruoy em wohS"
.gnol rof pu einrE ekahs ot demees reve gnihtoN
,tonk ydruts a ni gnirts eht fo sdne eht deit tub
,deknilb nooccar ehT .dednammoc yaJ
.retnuoc eht fo pot no ti gnittes ,tuo xob elttil eht gnillup dna esac eht fo kcab eht nepo gnidils
"?taht htiw od ot gniog uoy era tahW"
,neht hcnul rieht thguorb ssertiaw ehT ".won
.deilpmoc niW ".won yawa ti tuP"
",raey tsal tsuj s'tahT"
,kcen sih dnuora gnirts eht no nekot eht pu dleh eh hcihw ta
.niaga dednamed eh
.dias eh ",meht rof gnikool yllaiciffo si enoemos litnu taht tuoba yrrow ton s'teL" .deddon sicnarF ".morf
.lrig eht deksa einrE "?ecnis ti no srettel esoht htiw esle gnihtyna nees t'nevah uoY"
,deretne yeht sa dednuos lleb A
",gnitirw dna erutaretiL"
".niaga emoc esaelp dna
.hsac ydaer fo deen ni saw eh esuaceb meht ot ti dlos dah renwo eht taht em dlot yeht ,ti thguob I nehW"
.nwo sih htiw enod dah eh sa ti morf csid dnoces eht dednepsus dna ,gnirts eht fo eceip rehtona tuo derusaem ohw ,sicnarF ot ksid eht evag dna tekcop sih ni gud yaJ
.yadot litnu ti wonk t'ndid tsuj I
.ylirassecennu deralced sicnarF
.walc a htiw esool ti deirp eh sa