”!rab yag a retne uoy nehw lagelli semoceb wohemos
timda attog uoy tniop emos ta ,yteicos ni ytilauqe tnaw uoy fi ,noitingocer lagel tnaw uoy fi tub ,tnaw uoy lla ti eye-
”!srab fo hcnub a dediar lla uoy ecnis ,htnom a neeb neve t’nsaH“ .ylkciuq
!oot ereht raew ot gnidnamed er’uoy mrofinu eht was I dna ,saw I
,edirP yppaH  .stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,rab eht no tsif sih dedduht god eht ”,aibohpomoh emas nikcuf
”…rebmun ruoy si siht ,tiaW“
uoy ees yeht dnA .tuoba saw llawenotS tahw wonk yeht ,sdiar eht tuoba draeh yeht
,esoohc ot evah annog er’uoy nehT“ ”.efasnu leef
.ffo mih tuc arabypac ehT ”.ereh ton
”.em rof esnes ekam ti ekam os
maerts eht otni tuo gnikael ,niatnuom a rednu ero fo maes a ekil deirub ,eciov s’namrebod eht ni ytirecnis fo ecart a saw ereht elbissop saw ti dnA
ot ton riaf eb t’ndluow ti esuaceB
”?uoy dna meht neewteb ecnereffid eht llet ot desoppus sklof raluger su er’woH
”.yas ot tahw onnud …I“
...“ ”!eno ekirts s’taht tub ,kcab klat ot ecnahc ruoy teg ll’uoY !ti dloH“
,gnikaeps saw taht ,htuom latrom a ton ,yella eht erew ti fi sa ,yella eht nwod deohce ti ”,sevlesmeht yojne
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY.goD
,dedeen eb rehtruf fi ,noitanalpxe rehtruf yna roF .tsetorp
eht tahw s’taht ,gnitteg
snaem ’spoC llA‘ yhw s’tahT !od ot desu steg mrofinu taht tahw rof
su gnitcetorp er’yeht ekil detaert eb ot teg t’nod yeht dna ,tey t’nera yeht dna ,neeb t’nevah yeht tuB .sthgir lagel ruo fo edis eht no eb ot thguo ecilop eht ebyam ,haey“
tneloivnon dna lufwal rof stneduts ta gnitoohs dna ,gnitaeb
”-riS“ ”?ytinummoc siht fo trap a ro nortap a sa tnuoc t’nod ylneddus I ,petskcol ni kniht t’now I esuac tsuJ“
:ytiugibma on eb ereht teL
”,gnihtyna yas t’noD“
?ko ,ereht t’nsaw I“
netsil ot evah ton ot thgir eht ekiL .rab siht fo snortap eht fo sthgir eht tuoba erac I“
kcabhsup decaf ev’uoy yas uoY
”.pup ,edirp yppaH“ ”.edirP yppaH“
uoy fi neve ,su fo eno llits er’uoy ,eb ot ton esoohc uoy litnu esuaceB :snosaer fo ytnelp nevig evah ,spahrep ,dluoc arabypac ehT
,llawenotS sa tihs emas tcaxe ehT“
spoc ehT“ ”-ylbmessa lufwalnu na deralced neeb d’tahT“
,epoN“ ”-tsuj ,tnaw uoy revetahw ,ko ,eniF“ .wap
.uoy wonk t’nod yeht oS“
”.elpoep gnibrutsid er’uoy ,evael ro nwod ti peek rehtie ot uoy ksa ot evah annog m’I ,ris ,yeH“
...“ ”.rewsna eht ni detseretni t’nera uoy edulcnoc ot evah annog m’I esle ro ,taht od I elihw
”!yag gnieb namecilop a htiw ko—
,dewolleb arabypac eht ”!haeY“
.trihs-t sih no YTIRUCES drow eht revo smra sih dessorc arabypac ehT ”.enif ,erus kO“
,ytiludercni fo eton a pu kcip ot gnitrats saw eciov s’recnuob ehT ”!owt ekirts s’taht dna
”-riS“ ”?llA naem llA t’nseoD ”?emocleW xloF reeuQ llA“ yas rood tnorf taht t’nseoD“
pu wohs seod dna
,tops hcnurb ,aps ,esuohhtab ,bulc ecnad ,rab yreve ot gniklat
elddir a ot rewsna eht dlot neeb d’eh fi sa ,og ot denrut eh sa ,dednuos namrebod eht ”…thgirlA“
”.tnaw yeht tahw steg enoyrevE
.morf saw kcabhsup taht ohw wonk uoy wonk I os ,tnemtraped ruoy morf
”!su gnitcetorp trats yllautca yeht litnu
”!nni llawenotS eht ta dneirfyob tsal ym dna em fo serutcip tog I“ ,seye sih dellor god eht ”,esruoc gnikcuf fO“
”,toN“ ”-ecnanidro lahtel-non lla saw tahT“
,enoyna gnitruh morf uoy peek
levon gnimocpu na ni pu wohs lliw
,nwo uoy strohs ograc dna trihs olop gnirob tsom eht raew ,gard lluf raew ,ssenrah a raew ,gnoht a raeW
evissimbus a desiar namrebod ehT
.rewsna eht saw ti yhw dnatsrednu tey t’ndid tub
erom dah d’eh ro ,deklat eh nehw ,sdnah sih htiw evisserpxe yrev rehtie saw namrebod ehT ”!dam m’I thgir nmad er’uoY“
,gnitaitogen saw eh ekil tlef god eht ”,gniyrt ton m’I“
.eson sih hguorht dehgis arabypac ehT ”.sgniht owt
,llew :yas dluow ,pu dewohs yug taht nehw
emoh og uoy llit“
mrofinu eht ni er’uoy taht si uoy tuoba wonk yeht llA .etapicitrap ot ereh er’uoy wonk t’nod yehT .yag er’uoy wonk t’nod yehT
edistuo pets ew neht dna
,dnim ym egnahc ot yrt annaw uoy“
”.thgirlA“ ”?tog uoy ev’tahW“
”!riafnu s’tI ?krow ot raew I mrofinu eht fo esuac taht tuoba segnahc tahW
.swap delffab daerps arabypac ehT ”!wonk uoy
?t’nod ohw su fo esoht gnitaert neeb yeht ev’woh
.rab yag a nwod gnittuhs dna gnidiar spoc yb dekovorp toir saw ti
si yrots s’yadoT
,uoy dniheb nwod reddal eht skcik
…ekil taht kniht tsuj I ,gnihtyna
”.sdaeh s’elpoep ta me erif uoy nehw“
si deksa gnieb er’uoy lla esuaC“
,tuons s’god eht morf sehcni ,regnif elgnis a pu dleh arabypac eht ”,tuB
,gnissarah era ecilop yrtnuoc eht ssorca sesupmac no ,siht drocer I sa nevE
,krap eht yb revo erots koob cimoc eht neve
ediS“ .desserpminu yltcnitsid dekool arabypac ehT
”-t’ndluohs ,lleW“ ”.si ti nehw si
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.hguoht tuoba si siht tahw ton s’tahT .ebyam ,naem I“
”?efas leef annog yeht erA
!neht esnes ekam ti ekam llew ,hgU“
”…hU“ ”.evila neeb ev’I dna uoy naht regnol rof neeb sah ,ytinummoc eht ot
,eciov s’arabypac eht ni elbmur ediw-yella eht fo ecart a tsuj saw ereht
erawa er’uoy epoh d’I neht“
kcab tnew recnuob eht dnA
.ot deen uoy ezilaer uoy ecno ,retteb od ot ecnahc a teg t’ndluohs uoy naem t’nseod taht
”.nab emitefil a ta gnikool eb annog er’uoy ,rettal eht s’ti fi esuaC“ ”-ton s’tahT“
taerht a s’taht—poc a gnieb—
tpurretni ton attog uoy“
,eeS“ .hteet dehcnelc
,saw dias eh lla tuB .em evag ecno ydobemos enilefil eht uoy evig
.dednah neeb d’eh repap fo pils eht ta deknilb namrebod ehT
.edirP ta ecalp on evah spoc
...“ .mutamitlu lautxetbus eht eviecrep ot hguone rebos llits saw namrebod ehT ”.ecnahc ruoy s’ereh
,ekatsim on eb ereht teL
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
eb ll’I ,ecalp ym morf tsuj ton dnA“ ”!-yeH“
.gnitnar god emos fo ruoh na ot
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf seigolohtna ni pu nwohs sah krow esohw
ton er’uoy tahw s’tahT
,ot tnaw uoy nehw“
.noitanalpxe dedeen siht eveileb t’ndluoc eh fi sa
,kO“ ”!lla snaem llA“
,dnim ruoy kaeps ot teg llits uoY ?ko ,em ot lla ti nialpxe nac uoy dna
’,tcudnoC dweL‘ rof stekcit me evag ,tuo elpoep deggard
!mrofinu taht raew ot ton
ot gniyrt erew eh fi sa ,ria eht ni selcric gnicart erew swap s’namrebod eht ”…ot
tuo eb dluoc ecrof eht no nemow dna nem rehto eht taht os ,saw I ohw rof pu dnats ot dah I drah woH“ .htob rO
”?sevlesmeht pu gnikaeps tuohtiw yas ot evah uoy gnihtyna ta don dna pu tuhs ot enoyreve tcepxe tsuj uoy od ro ,gnidnatsrednu ni detseretni yllautca uoy erA .rehtruf yna og ew erofeb deifiralc gnihtemos teg attog eW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”?rof sdnats ti tahw wonk uoy taht ”,BACA“ esarhp eht draeh ev’uoy taht emussa annog m’I“
,deunitnoc arabypac eht ”,ti dias uoy tuB“
.renroc eht dehcaer yeht nehw deppots arabypac ehT ”?huh ,poc a
?ytilauqe egairram tuoba tahw
,tra llaw gnigaruocne yllacihpargonrop fo daetsni ngis gnikraP oN dna itiffarg
tcaxe eht decaf ev’I
:noitaitogen on eb nac ereht
”?edirP yppaH‘ tuobawoH“
”?tluaf ym taht si ,naem I“
”.yas ot tahw onnud llits I …I“
”.htiw smret gnikaeps no ton m’I seno eht nevE“
,yaw rehto eht kool d’ynam woH ?dnabsuh rieht ,rehtaf rieht ,rehtorb rieht sa yug taht ot emoh og meht fo ynam woH ?ebircsed taht seod sreciffo wollef ruoy fo ynam woH .snugtohs dna skcurt eht htiw stogib tuo-depmurt esoht ,tsriF“
saw tI ”.emoclew t’nera smrofinu ni spoc gniyas edarap eht revo dam er’uoY .ereht ni eltbus yltcaxe gnieb t’nerew uoY“
gniyrt ton m’I ,kooL“
,floWcaM boR yb ”llA snaeM llA“
”.lla snaem lla ,esoohc uoy revehcihw tub rehto eht lla ro gniht eno lla
neht dnA .rebos ti ekam uoy dna ,eciohc ruoy ekam uoY .hguorht siht kniht dna emoh og uoY“
”.ereht poc a s’ereht fi
tniop emos ta ,aibohpomoh tuohtiw dlrow a ot teg annog reve er’ew fi
.walc a no motpmys hcae detsil arabypac ehT ”.renroc a otni dekcab dna ,derit dna ,knurd er’uoy tuB“
.ces eno ,kO“ .eson sih fo egdirb eht dehcnip arabypac ehT ”-taht ecidujerp dna etah rof sdnats ti ,haey ,hU“
”…eno doog a eb athguo sihT
,ekil tub …did yrotsih fo lla ni poc rehto yna tahw rof em egduj ot riaf ton s’ti dnim reveN“
”.llawenotS wonk uoy em llet esaelP“ ”.enif...“
.tnias a ton ytiruces rab saw eh dna ,hsi-elgnis er’uoy ekil sdnuos ti dna ,eugnot sih htiw od dluoc god a sgniht eht dna sgod rof gniht a dah eh esuaceB
esucxe“ ,retaw daert
”.emas eht yas ll’thginot rab eht ni elpoep eht fo tsom dnA .wal a ekorb me fo eno ton nehw ,gnitsetorp rof ylimaf dna sdneirf ym“
,htuom sih denepo god ecilop ehT ”!llA‘
.taht tsniaga wal on s’ereht ,hceeps eerf ot thgir sih tog s’eh
”.hguone eurt s’taht ,tahw wonk uoY“
”?niaga sdiar eht dna sag raet eht revo og attog I oD“ ”-neeb ev’eW“
tcirtsid reeuq s’ytic nwo yM
,flesruoy raeh ton uoy oD“
.t’ndid uoy seno eht tsniaga ,esohc tsuj uoy elpoep eht morf troppus emos deen thgim uoy …od uoy FI
edirP nosaer elohw ehT
ytilibisnopser no gnittup er’uoy ,mrofinu taht no tup uoY .snaem mrofinu ni ’inU‘
”.ot deen I erus m’I sselnu ffo ydobyna gnittuc ton m’I .lla snaem llA“
”!desimorp I srab rehto esoht lla gniliame thginot gnidneps m’I dna noitpurretni erom enO“
sDEL deroloc-edirp naht rehtar sthgilteerts til-tsuj fo emorhconom deroloc ruflus :yella eht ni tuo dlrow tnereffid yrev a
.ssab gnidnuop fo daetsni ssaprednu yawhgih tnatsid fo raor llud eht
”-nrobbuts uoy ,uoy htiw eerga ot gniyrt m’I“
?meht ecrofne annog s’ohw lleW“ ”?me tuoba tahW“
,dessag raet gnitteg saw I .saw I erehw uoy llet nac I tub ,0202 fo remmus erew uoy erehw ksa ton dna ,ereh luftcat eb annog m’I
.leets sa drah seye sih ,ynots ecaf sih ,dessorc erew smra s’recnuob ehT
.htooms dna teiuq ,grebeci na ekil dehcaorppa arabypac ehT
”.tsil ’timdA toN oD‘ eht no tup uoy evah
,semit lareves ,niaga ti tuhs
,god eht ta wap a devaw arabypac eht ”,lausac sserd NAC uoy ylraelc dnA“
”.sliame esoht dnes attog I ton ro rehtehw wonk I os esohc uoy tahw em egassem uoy
sgniht ekam dluoc I“
,hcihW .si taht worromot eciohc thgir eht ekam uoy FI
metsys a tuoba s’tI .lla ta UOY tuoba toN .nosrep a sa era uoy ohw ro ,edisni leef uoy tahw tuoba ton s’ti ’sdratsaB erA spoC llA‘ yas ew nehW“
,anueL yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
”!?si ti woh ees uoy ,erehT“ ”.gnitnar
.hguone ton ebyam tuB
.waht gnirps eht htiw
,eno eriuqer ot ton demees arabypac eht tub ”,dnoceS“
er’uoy oS“   ”.sknahT ?em rof rood tnorf eht revoc ot wonk ogeiD tel neht dna ,bat ym no ,erom eno pup siht evig ,nalyD !ris ,uoy knahT“ ”.erus ,ti kcuf...“
.gninialpxe m’I tahw s’tahT“ .denihw god eht
,eman a kcab tib eh
,edirP ot og ot stnaw tsuj ohw ydobemoS“
,edarap eht ta sruls gnituohs strats dna nugtohs a htiw pukcip tuo-depmurt a ni laoc gnillor pu swohs togib emos nehW
”?swal emirc etah tuoba tahW
,sdnoces evif roF“ ”-tuB“
,dnim ym gnikaeps rof tsuj tuo em dekcik taht ecalp a rof drah yrev
,llab ocsid euqitna dna
.boj ym od ot teg I dna ,gnineve rieht yojne dna xaler ot teg sklof eseht
”!ylsuoires ti ekat I tub
,gnihsilbuP sirneF morf
yrev pu namrebod eht gnirebos saw—gnihctaw t’nerew yeht dneterp ot gniyrt skaeb dna selzzum fo lufdnah a—yella eht fo dne rehto eht ssorca ,enil ecnartne eht ro ria thgin-ylerab looc eht rehtiE
.eciov sih desiar arabypac eht emit tsrif eht roF
.erutaerc-flah tenretni ruoy
.erutaerc flah tenretni ruoy ,anueL yb daeR
ytinummoc reeuq dna ecilop—lla er’ew naem ot evah ll’taht
.saw ’lla uoy‘ ohw no yrassecen saw noitarobale oN
!gniyas tsuj ma I“ ”?nam
”?tnemtraped eht morf decaf I ecnatsiser hcum woh dnatsrednu uoY“ .wef a naht
eb t’nac uoY .su tsniaga flah rehto eht dna su htiw flah eb t’nac uoY .pup
efas leef ton ot dlrow eht ni nosaer nmad yreve tog ev’ohw seno eht neve ,lla snaem llA .su fo lla rof s’edirp :tnemugra siht fo gninnigeb“
.siht rof rewsna on dah god ehT
.ekops taht flesti ,doohrobhgien eht ,teerts eht erew ti fi sA
,mrofinu rieht gniraew enoemos ot taht od ot gnilliw erew yeht fI
,snaem noitutitsnoc nikcuf eht ni ’elbaneilani‘
.yrots s’yadot ot uoy refer ew
,kO“ ”.pu rebos dna
”?mih ta ecneloiv lanoitutitsni nialpxe annog tsuj uoY
,eye na tsol ylraen d’ohw ,yllaer ,dik a tsuj ,rumel a fo yromem eht tsniaga waj sih dehcnelc recnuob eht
,delooc eciov s’recnuob eht ”,kooL“ ”!revetahW“
”!enif dias I“ ”!taht ot uoy gnidloh m’I“ ”.revetahw ,enif...“
...“ ”?ko ,won rof snoitseuq eht dloH“
.tsetorp lufecaep ot thgir lanoitutitsnoc ym gnisicrexe rof ,htiw moor kaerb eht ni tuo gnah uoy reveohw yb ,ereh morf skcolb flah a n’eerht
.ytilaturb ecilop tsniaga toir a saw edirp tsrif ehT
”.erofeb meht morf noitanimircsid decaf ev’uoy ,dias uoy ekiL
”!noitanimircsid s’tI“
”?kool taht htiw s’tahW“
”.siht tuobawoh ,kO“
,skcirb looc eht tsniaga kcab sredluohs sih denael recnuob ehT ”thgirlA“
”…tserra dna taeb seugaelloc ruoy dehctaw I
”.mrofinu ni renroc eht dnuora emoc
,rab eht dniheb gip aeniug eht ta erutseg ot kcab delrihw namrebod eht
ohw rekciltoob nikcuf rehtona eb ot tuo gninrut morf uoy peek ot si nosaer niam eht fi neve esuaceB .tnaem taht tahw wonk t’ndid
floWcaM boR yb ”llA snaeM llA“
”?wonk uoy d’woH“
”!uoy tub enoyna fo evitcepsrep eht morf siht tuoba kniht tsuj
,sdrow rof delbmuf god eht ”…tub
.elttil a tsuj ,hcnelcnu sredluohs sih tel arabypac ehT ”.thgirlA“
”.yrros ,thgiR“
?mih tserra annog s’ohw
.gnikool dab ton er’uoY ?tahW“
lleW“ ”!em t’nsaw tahT
.dessag raet gnieb 0202 enuJ fo yteritne eht tneps
.sthgir rieht yawa ekat ot emit s’ti nehw no tup elpoep
”.emit taht t’nsi won tuB“ ”!uoy knahT“
hguorht delworg namrebod ehT ”.timmad...“
”?taht fo duorp eb ot teg I t’noD
,sag raet eht rebmemer yeht tub“
.evah yeht ebyam dnA“
.efil sih rof thgif ot tuoba erew eh fi sa kcen sih dexelf god eht
!ereh esle enoyreve sa“
”?taht ekil sgniht yas uoy nehw ecidujerp ton si woH“
,knird a uoy yub ll’I“ .etalacseed
drow eht tahw s’taht ,taht od t’nac
”!melborp a tog t’nod ew dna
.dnif dluoc eh lla saw ”?yhw“ tub
htao na koot I !no eb ot tnaw uoy edis eht no era ecilop eht taht
ylneddus ylno tub ,teerts eht no tuo lagel yletelpmoc eb d’taht ,srab thgiarts ni ti od sklof thgiarts nehw lagel yltcefrep s’taht roivaheb revo sesnecil rouqil denetaerht
rehtie er’uoY .raey eht fo tser eht su tsniaga neht dna enuJ ni su fo eno
.gniraew saw eh strohs ograc dna trihs olop eht ta nwod ecnalg ot egru eht thguof god ehT
,taht ot pu gnivil t’nera spoc emos ebyam dna ,snezitic eht lla evres dna tcetorp ot
?segdab rieht esol ton dna
.krow rehto sih ot
.tra llaw evitacovorp yllufetsat-os-ton dna ,sthgil lufroloc ,cisum duol fo eelem yrosnes eht hguorht mih ta eralg ot denrut namrebod ehT ”!?sthgir ym tuoba erac t’nod uoy ,hO“
ot emit saw ti dediced arabypac ehT
.egap yrruFoS sih no
.dednetni d’eh naht rellams hcum saw eciov s’namrebod ehT ”?os ,haeY“
”llA snaeM llA“ saw sihT
.mialc siht deined ron demrifnoc rehtien god ehT ”’.degnahc evah sgniht ,oga yrutnec a flah saw taht tub‘ ,yas ot tuoba erew uoy gnitteb m’I
”.recnuob eht m’I dnA .arabypaC“ ”!em ezinortap ot revaeb emos deen t’nod I“
.yas ot detnaw eh gnihtemos dnif ot demees reven tub
”?tey klat ot teg I erehw trap eht ta ew erA“
enoyna ekam ot“ ,won