ssecorp eht gnitaepeR
elohliat ruoy otni kcab ecnartne eht tub
,sgnul ruoy morf htaerb eht sehsinab htaehs/tils ruoy ssorca skcil tfos wef A
-aera taht esolc ot
,eb ot erutan ruoy ton s'tI
noitseuq ni repmihw tniaf a tuo tel uoy sa deb eht ni flesruoy gnitfihs ylthgil
,dnim ruoy stnuah tsuj noitseuq ehT
.uoy ot railimaf yrev era taht seno
edis ot edis hcuop derruf taht gnitfihs yltneg
.ruf sih fo selkcit thgil eht morf ffo flesti desolc ti ylthgit dna ylkciuq woh fo sseldrager
,tlef ylisae si loot ekil-eninac eht fo tfahs niam ehT
saw deen neddus A .loot s'raeb eht detaoc dna
,drah os ydob sih gnippirg morf eros ylraen era selcsum ruoY
,sih otno elzzum ruoy dekcol uoy litnU
.ylthgit meht depsarg sllaw evitisnes ruoy sa
taoc s'raeb eht gnihcnerd dna
,ni desserp eh sa
:nruter llits snoitseuq esoht
?ssilb fo evaw yvaeh A
.elzzum desolc ruoy nihtiw gnis ylraen uoy gnikam
,woleb sehsarht liat ruoY
,emit siht rehtraf hcum ton
,emit tsrif eht rof dnA
.rehtooms yltnacifingis si
natraB morf slworg wef A
emit siht reivaeh hcuM
.eromyna ydob nwo ruoy lortnoc ot elbanu
.daeh sih barg ot
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,elddim ruoy nwod gnidnecsed llitS
tneuqerf erom dna erom emoceb ot gnitrats stnerrot renni ehT
ssenkrad eht nihtiw dnirg sllih etihw esoht sa dorp wolS
,ot stnaw flesruoy fo trap emoS
.xes gnitnaw otni ti etalupinam
.niaga dorp taht leef dna nwod draug ruoy llup uoy
,uoy edisni nopaew euqinu eht ot desu tog uoy sa
ssilb fo etats railimaf a
.tuo sllews ti sa pit ruoy ssorca gnippal ylwols eugnot tfos taht tuo gnikaM
.revo ekat stcnitsni ruoy sa
,ti wonk uoy erofeb dna etatsorp ruoy tsniaga gnihctiwt nopaew siH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
stnemom lareves rof ti fo tuo ooT
,gnimmuc mih saw ti taht decnivnoc ylraeN
,taoc etihw sih gnipsarg
.sruoy tsniaga ylesolc daeh sih gnillup
flesruoy dnif uoy taht drah os mih gnippirg
yrrulb emoceb ot snigeb noisiv ruoY
.ylthgils enihw uoy gnikam
.shtaerb gnipsag htiw gnis dna tnap ot uoy gnisuac
,ydob ruoy hguorht evaw evissam a tnes erusserp llams a hcuS
.ylthgit uoy gnitnuom llabruf eht ezeeuqs dna
.hguor ylthgils saw taht ssik peed a htiw eno
,erusaelp fo etats tnatsnoc a ni uoy gnipeeK
tceted ylthgils od uoy ,siht lla gniruD
kcen ruoy tsniaga elzzum etihw taht fo sekorts wef A
.tsrif dexaler gnieb tuohtiw gniht a hcus fo gnitpecca eb ylisae ton lliw ydob ruoY"
...ot deen uoy tub ,slacov ruoy htiw ti yas tonnac uoY
...raer ruoy gnidnuop neeb s'raeb eht gnol woh fo kcart esol uoY
hcuop taht tceted uoy nehw ydob ruoy nihtiw ohce ot nigeb sgninraw esohT
,slacov detpurretni wef a naht erom gnihton esaeler llits uoY
.tuhs hcnelc uoy dna slruc egadneppa gnol ruoy elihw
.sruoy tsniaga pu edils ydob yffulf sih leef uoy sa
.tohsmuc sih fo emulov lluf eht eviecer ot gniog er'uoy dna
tciderp ot elba uoy gnikaM
,hctorc ruoy ot esolc tog elzzum taht nehw
.uoy dootsrednusim eh fi rednow uoy erehw tniop eht ot
.emit emas eht ta ti ot trofmoc gniveiler siht dleh ti tub
....worg ot nageb ti elihw saw ti tahw fo kniht ot
.desopmoc ylbidercni flesruoy dnif uoy ,nopaew ruoy morf striuqs wef a dna
tsaeb eht morf erusaelp fo slworg ydaets eht tuo gnikam yleraB
ni edils eralf taht gnileef dna
,ylwols pu sllews ti sa
!tniop siht ta elbissopmi ylraelc si taht ksat a ,tuo llup ot yrt ylthgil
ylleb ruoy ot tonk kciht sih fo esab eht morf srenni ruoy gnidoolF
pal hcae fo snoitom eht sa
.elohliat ruoy revo nwod edils
!tuo gnillup detrats natraB nehw erom neve wohemos nehT
spih ruoy ot nwod gnihcaeR
gnimoc era stsurht evissergorp eht nehw
,niaga nwod daeh sih sserp uoy dna
.uoy otni sesserp yltneg raeb eht sa
.senips esoht htiw gnola
mraw uoy gnipeek taoc etihw tfos siH
.taoc sih otni peed knis swap ruoy gnittel dna
,rodxeD fo eman eht rednu
...nrecnoc htiw yraew worg
?timbus uoy fi nosrep a fo ssel uoy ekam ti seoD
sgninraw eht sserppus ot tib elttil a tuo ffuh ot uoy gnivaeL
,skcil wef a uoy sevig eugnot taht sa
rebmem ruoy tsniaga gnitnuB
.ecnavda sih nwod wols ot gnipoh sedis rewol sih tsniaga sserp sgel dnih ruoy
.sraey 8 ylraen rof ybboh eht ni neeb s’ohw retirw nwonknu ylevitaler a si ohw
setunim lareves retfA
.ti fo pot no stser ti sa
,elttil a tsuj etag ruoy sretne yllanif pit s'ti sa
.shtaerb neewteb raor uoy elihw uoy htaenrednu gniddeb eht kaos dna sedis ruoy nwod nur lla ti gnileeF
!-uoy edisni eit ton ot
.llaw ruoy gnola aera evitisnes repus emos hcuot eralf eht neht
esuap a sekat natraB ,revewoH
!...retsaf dna retsaf ylevissergorp devom
liat ruoy revo reivaeh wohemos gnileef sih fo hcuop yffulf tahT
,netfo erom ti leef ot detnaw uoy taht
.sselhtaerb raen uoy sevael taht noitom elpmis rehtona
lla ta emit on gnikaT
.tixe ruoy nihtiw yaw s'ti gnihsup
.tuo gnillol eugnot
.ti nihtiw tfahs taht ot desu steg ti sa
elohliat ruoy nihtiw moor eht gnihcterts ylthgil
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.srehto sdrawot emas eht enod ev'uoy semit ynam woh fo sseldrager ,ereht retne ot desoppus ton si ti taht gninraw retfa gninraw gnitceteD
.niaga yrt ot mih rof daeh ruoy sdrawot taoc s'raeb eht gut yltneg dna
.ylthgit wollip gnivil eht ecarbme uoy sa cinap a ni ti gnizeeuqs
;drow retteb a fo kcal rof ,lleW
.edisrednu dekaos s'natraB htiw nopaew gniyarps llits ruoy sehsiuqs taht eglub a gnitaerC
,enola hcuot evitisnes reehs hguorht eralf ekil-eninac eht tuo ekam ot uoy gniwollA
htgnel ruoy gnola sedils ti sa gnihctiwt
hself der taht fo pit eht leef nac uoy gniraewS
xaler uoy gnileef
,ylthgit noinapmoc s'gnineve ruoy gnipsarG
ycrem eht ta uoy gnivael dna
.seidob owt ruoy neewteb ylivaeh muc uoy sa
,uoy edisni gnidliub snigeb gnihtemos sa sisylarap fo etats a ni thguaC ?ebyam lareveS
.esnopser a evig ot deen uoy tuB
llits niamer raeb eht gnitteL
?gnikam noisiced evislupmI ?tnemeticxe-revO
,deb tew tfos ruoy ni tser flesruoy leef uoy sa
...nehT ?ti ekil t'nod uoy fi tahW
,dne raer ruoy tsniaga pu sserp pit sih dna
.pirg ruoy nethgit uoy dna rehtruf elttil a steg ti sa
eno siht piks nac uoy
.ylleb ruoy otni rehtag ot snigeb erusserp taht sa
.taerht tfos eht ot desu teg uoy tel ot sgnaf llud esoht morf spsarg dna sllup eltneG
lliw ruoy tsniaga
!uoy spots gnihtemos tuB
,xiriT natraB yb
.deslup tonk s'raeb taht litnu raef htiw ti gnicalper dna
gnilims morf flesmih pleh ot elbanu
.lavo egral a ni rediw dna
.rewol evom ot strats eh sa
sllaw renni ruoy nwod delkcirt ti sa ylduol tnap ot uoy gniwollA
?tnaw uoy tahw taht sI
.sgel ruoy neewteb gnitser
.tixe ruoy raen ssenesned egnarts a
,sredluohs sih tsniaga nethgit swalc ruoY  !seunitnoc
.edis ot edis sgniws liat yffulf gnol taht elihw
,od ot dah reve ev'uoy gniht tsedrah eht s'ti fi sa ,dnA
,gniyfirret si ti sa gniticxe sa s'tI
tnemrot ylraen erew
.uoy fo tuo gnillup ylwols erofeb
sllaw lufedirp esoht nwod gnillup yllaniF .don uoy
llabruf eht fo dloh gnikat yllautca
.od yllaer uoy ,eno mih evig ot tnaw uoy dnA
...neve elbarusaelP
.gninthgil fo tlob a ekil uoy stih ti ,ecno ta llA
spih ruoy no dekrow eh sa
,eugnot railimaf eht tsniaga sborht rebmem ruoy sa tsehc ruoy evael
ssik tfos a tuons ruoy gnivig dna daeh ruoy gnitnub ylwols
.sesuac ti erusaelp esnemmi eht ta niaga taoc sih otni walc ot uoy gnisuac dna
.drah mih pirg uoy sa tcatnoc nopu ylraen
.emit ot emit morf noitcetorp ruoy gniddorp
,srenni ruoy tsniaga gnidils senips tfos ehT
?owT ?ruoh nA ?setunim neT
,elahxe gnirepmihw a htiW
ti fo noinapmoC eht nraw neve t'nac uoY
.sllaw s'rewot ruoy dehsaw eugnot taht sa tnecsed eht gnivol
,won epacse on s'erehT
.moor eht fo ssenkrad eht hguorht draeh era srepsihw s'raeb ehT
.esnopser ni uoy morf don yhs A
.yawa gnihsup ton tub
tsrif ruoy s'tI" .ssenkrad eht ni scsid nworb esoht ta gnikool elihw
aera renni taht ot sehctiwt thgils ehT
,niaga liat ruoy gnola detceted era sllab yvaeh esoht litnu toN
.sehctulc tnatsnoc s'ti htiw ti yduts ydob ruoy gnittel dna
”4# uoY roF llA“ saw sihT
.edisni repeed detceted saw eralf taht elihw
a ni deniatbo yllausu s'taht
;detrats selcyc ehT
gnikael trats ot erp taht rof
os od ot shtaerb wef a gnikat
eciton ylerab uoy taht os hcum os
.deeserp fo stnerrot lareves ekil sleef tahw gnisaeler erofeb ygrene htiw smuh ylraen ti sa
tnemom a rof sgnileef lufssilb taht lla gnisuap yllautcA
,htaerb ruoy hctac ot uoy rof stnemom wef a gnitiaw neht nevE
.tlef saw niap oN ...revewoH
.deb eht otni flah reppu ruoy desserp eh sa rrup peed a esaeler tsaeb eht gnikaM
.syaw tnereffid fo rebmun
.kaep sti sehcaer msagro nwo ruoy sa
.nalp eht saw os ro ,gnineve eht hguorht tpels uoy sa
,sllaw renni ruoy dna sbmil ruoy htiw htoB
sdrawpu gnillup liat ruoy
suoiciled taht fo triuqs yvaeh a leef uoy dna
,tuo llup ot natraB ta repmihw ylraen uoY
.ti eveirter ot egadneppa taht dna
:4# uoY roF llA
.liat ruoy fo esab eht ta tser dna nwod edils
.elohliat ruoy ni gniworg si nolemretaw nmad a raews uoy sa
.ecaf sih ees ot sdrawpu daeh sih dellup dna
.ylleb sih dekaos uoy sa dnim ot demees reven llabruf eht taht eno
loot ruoy sdrawot tnerruc a ekil noitalumitsrevo na sdnes
,niaga edisni serutnev raeb eht sa
sredluohs s'natraB ot pu dehcaer uoy sa tlef
,raer ruoy sretne eralf eritne sih dna
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,don a htiw eunitnoc ot mih noitom uoy daetsnI
...tey muc t'nsah eH ...eH
.eugnot nwo ruoy gnola tlef yeht tfos woh fo sseldrager
,ta ffocs ot gnihton erew spit llud rieht dnA
,tsrif ta gniraes tsomlA
,elzzum etihw taht no kcol ruoy esaeler ot uoy rof stnemom nezod lareves sekat tI
...etiuq gnileef llits
.sevren raer ruoy detalumitsrevo ngised s'raeb eht sa
erom ti od ot gnitnaw reven
.niaga pu strats raeb eht tub
"?sey ,emit
rehgih pu wollip gnivil eht gnillup
,elzzum taht otni gnitsurht tsiser uoy tnemom a roF
sdrawrof hcaer uoy sa
,detrela era sesnefed ruoY
.smra dna sredluohs ruoy segassam eh sa
,nwod daeh s'natraB fo kcab eht gnisserp erofeb regnol elttil a rof tuo dloh ot elba ylnO
.selahxe sih fo htmraw eht yb deteerg gnieb
ylleb ruoy gnikaoS
-niaga nwod draug ruoy ecrof uoy dna
,sedis ruoy gnola gnidils eugnot tahT
yawflah tuons taht gniteem morf flesruoy gniniartseR
,evisnefed eht no seog ydob ruoy sa
,erofeb ekil uoy gniddorP
.srenni ruoy tsniaga burcs meht leef dna kcab llup ot detrats natraB nehw enihw a gnisaeleR
?tuo no-ereh morf natraB dna uoy neewteb drawkwa ti ekam spahreP
stnemevom tneitap ehT
.niaga dees fo sepor ykcits ffo gnirif er'uoy
.htaerb ruoy hctac uoy stel dna
.tug renni ruoy ni rehtag smaerts mraw wef a
.yawa dellup si sih fo htaehs tfos taht sa ydob ruoy nwod
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
kcen ruoy nwod tlef era stnub tnatsnoc ehT
,ecneirepxe eht ot dedda rehtruf ylno taht erusserp thgils a gniviG
elzzum nwo ruoy nihtiw saw ti nehw ezis lautca s'ti gnillaceR
.gniht a hcus tneverp ot yrt ot pu sllup liat taht
.nepo uoy daerps eralf taht gnitceted yltnatsni
,teY .snwodkcol dna
srepsihw natraB ".yakO"
,htworg llams yreve htiw erusaelp fo romert egral a gnitaerC
.rewsna na rof stiaw yltneitap raeb eht sa lluks ruoy nihtiw ohce ti gnittel
uoy gnivael tsomlA
.nruter on fo tniop eht tsap ecar uoy sa enihw gniniarts a morf edisa
,sey ,tsrif ta gninrecnoC
.dloh sti sesae ydob ruoy litnu yltneitap gnitiaw dna
kcen s'natraB revo taeh fo llaw a gnisaeler
.sevael ti sa niaga tuo uoy hcterts tsomla eralf taht leef uoy sa ssem gnirepmihw a
regral eslup ti gnileef llitS
elohliat ruoy edisni tsuj eglub taht gnileeF
.enod naht dias reisae hguohT .xaler
,niaga aera laiceps taht tsniaga sesserp eralf taht sa uoy nihtiw peed htgnel eritne eht gnitceteD
,ti ot esolc gnieb taoc yffulf sih fo aedi eht ot desu teg dne raer ruoy gniwollA
yojne esaelP
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
sih fo htaehs yffulf taht gnitceted ylisae
.draug lla evomer dna
.liat ruoy otni tsurht spih esoht sa
.seye ruoy esolc dna kcab daeh ruoy tser uoy ,won roF
,llehs s'ti fo tuo emoc ot loot ruoy degaruocne egadneppa s'wam taht kcil retfa kciL
.uoy nihtiw peed deirub doohraeb sih fo hcni yreve tuo ekam ot elba
gnitrap erofeb ti elkcit ruf dna sreksihw sih gnittel dna
.os gniod elihw taoc sih otni walc dna
ytiniffAruF no krow sih fo lla weiv nac uoY
,erofeb ekil xaler ot yrt ot uoy egaruocne niaga ecno skcil dna stnub s'raeb ehT
,niaga ni sserp llabruf eht gnileeF
,raeb egral eht guh yltneg uoY .gnihtemos yaS
"?tnaw uoy tahw taht sI"   xiriT natraB yB
,niaga ecarb tahT  .repeed elttil a
.ysatsce htiw ydob ruoy gnidaolrevo
ro egagne ot gniyrt ton
.wols detrats natraB
sserts fo semit eseht gnirud yllaicepse
,pot ot mottob morf raeb eht yb dehsaw gnitteG
erusaelp fo sevaw eht lla morf gnitfihs ydob ruoY
!uoy edisni repeed dna repeed pit taht leef ot gnitnaw dna nwod wols ot mih gnitnaw fo etamelats siht ni thguaC
.smees ti ,tseb wonk did raeb ehT ".tsrif
elzzum nwo sih nihtiw noitseuq ni repmihw uoy gnikam
.etag ruoy fo edistuo tsuj detceted si pit taht nehw yllaicepse
.tuons ruoy fo edis eht fo tuo sllol eugnot ruoy litnu
.gnimlehwrevo oot semoceb tsuj erusaelp eht sa
.nopaew ruoy revo
,ydob reppu ruoy no stser raeb ehT
-ydob ruoy sekorts eh sa ecnelis eht kaerb ot gnihtynA
srenni ruoy ekar senips tfos esoht gnittel yllaeR
llew lluf gniwonk
?eveicer ot ekil tlef yllaer ti tahw siht sI ...sI
.elzzum eritne sih fo stsiwt wols eht
,pots t'nseod ti tuB
.krow sih eunitnoc ot llabruf eht rof hguone smra ruoy ni selcsum eht sexaler dna
stnap yvaeh lareveS
”4# uoY roF llA“
did yllausu eh ekil meht gnisserac dna
,nwo sih htiw ti ta spal raeb eht sa eugnot ruoy lortnoc ot elba yleraB
.noinapmoC derih ruoy fo
,srepmihw gniniarts esaeler ot natraB rof ylnO
.mih pots ll'uoy fi tset ot sdorp rewol dna
rediw sllaw renni ruoy gnihcterts
efil ruoy ni erp hcum os gnisaeler reven
sesaeler nwo yrev ruoy lavir ot trats nihtiw syarps ehT
,sdrawkcab pets rehtona ekat raeb eht leef ot ylnO
ti tlef tsal uoy ecnis reggib nettog s'ti gniraewS
scsid nworb esoht gnikaM
htaerb ruoy esol ot uoy gnisuac
neppah ot tuoba si tahw rehtegot gnittup etiuq ton
!tixe ruoy tsniaga pu gnisserp htaehs sih
.raer ruoy nihtiw reggib dna reggib steg eglub sih sa rethgit llabruf eht pirg ot ygrene deriuqca taht lla dnepxe si od nac uoy lla ,sseldrageR
.kcen ruoy fo edis eht skcil eugnot der taht sa kcab ruoy no tser ot gniunitnoC
yduts fo sretemitnec wef artxe esoht rof uoy sdrawot gnikcor yllanoisaccO
?!tey muc t'nsah eH
wam taht otni ti gnikat ylthgiL
,liat ruoy pu gnivom hcuop yffulf tahT
.ydob ruoy hguorht elppir sevaw eht sa htgnel ruoy nwod dna pu raeb eht gnilbbird tsomla dna daeh sih no wap eno gnipeek ,revewoH
gnissarrabme ti gnidnif ylraen dna
.hsulb htiw gninrub daeh ruoy leef uoy sa htaerb rof gnipsag
,emit taht gnirud yrarbil eht etiuq flesmih tliub s’eH
:taht tsuj od ot gniyrt dna mih ta gniddon tsuj niaga ecnO
.raer ruoy otni desaeler teg tloj mraw a tlef uoy
.uoy revo llabruf eht dnuora snethgit pirg ruoy sa hsulb htiw wolg ecaf ruoy sekam ylraen taht noitseuq A
.dne sti ta ssik a rof ni og elzzum taht gnileef erofeb pit ot esab
,erips ruoy hguorht erp fo epor kciht rehtona gnidnes dna etatsorp ruoy tsniaga gnisserp yllanoisaccO
.ediskcab ruoy doolf erp egnaro
,niaga ecno tuB  .ecalp ni deliaN
.setunim erom wef a tsuj rof repmihw a htiw gniggeb
skcil wef a kcen ruoy gnivig dna gnilzzun llitS
?si ti yas enilno srehto sa doog sa ti si
ssensuoicsnoc esol uoy sa pu uoy gnillif
.ssecorp gniyt eht hguorht ydob ruoy eldarc ylthgil ot seunitnoc eh sa
?pots ot mih llet uoY ?tahW
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ylduol psag ot llabruf eht sesuac hcnelc rehtonA
yltneitap noitcetorp s'ti fo tuo worg yltneg ti gnittel natraB
.emit eht nevig esaeler nac llabruf siht hcum woh tsuj
,slangis dexim dnes ylbissop nac noitisop sih hguohT
.liat ruoy fo esab eht dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
tserof etihw eht nihtiw hctiwt loot nwo ruoY
tsehc dna kcen ruoy pu gnitnub
os hcum oS  !...gnillarhtnE
.rewsna na hcus htiw gnillats dnim ruoy
tfahs s'llabruf eht sa
.niaga ecno nwodtnuoc eht trats ot natraB rof ylsuovren don uoy dna
edisni rehtruf elttil A
,llits wollip gnivil taht ecarb uoy sa
uoy otni dekcol yletelpmoc si tonk s'raeb eht
,sesnefed yzal won ruoy pu tup ot gnitpmettA
.seirots trohs ot slevon morf gnignar
.natraB eman derreferp eht rednu yrruFoS ro
.niaga snoitom sih pu trats mih leef dna
skcil wef a uoy gniviG
wardhtiw ot snigeb natraB retfa nevE
.sivlep ruoy hcuot eson kcalb taht leef dluoc uoy litnu nwod ti gnicrof tsuj dna tsurht a rof
,od ot noinapmoC eht diap uoy tahw s'tahT .mottob A ...llew
elttil a tsuj deb eht ffo gnitfil
sllabruf yvaeh esoht leef nac uoy nehw yllaicepse
.uoy edisni peed erutnev egnaro fo tloj yvaeh a gnitceted yllanoisacco elihw yllacitamard ydob ruoy gnitalumits dna
snoitom s'ti ni daed rewot der taht gnippotS
,rae ruoy ot txen
.dessap yeht sa sllaw ruoy gnola yhpargillac rieht gningis senips eht htiw
gnilzzum eht yojne uoy gnittel
,sdnirg ralucric htiw gnitratS
daeh dna pit mrif ehT
noisserpxe lufssilb ruoy ta
,krad eht ni yzah elttil a si ezag ruoY
,uoy gniretne tlef era egnaro fo stnerrot tsrif esoht nooS
?sdrawno sesserp eh fi tahW
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.won tlef pit taht egral woh
.sedis ruoy ekorts swap esoht elihw edisrednu ruoy gnola tuons taht gnihsurb
ydob ruoy pu pets-flah rehtona ekat natraB gnileeF
,truh ot gniog erew deraef ylraen uoy gnihtemoS
.dnoces yrev taht naht
.nac yeht sa hcum sa xelf lla yeht tub
.emit emas eht ta natraB gnihcnerd yletelpmoc dna edisrednu ruoy otno tnerrot retfa tnerrot gnihcnuaL
,xiriT natraB yb
,ylthgit mih otno gnilc uoy sa snoitom eht otni mrof eritne sti tup ot gnitrats ydob yffulf eritne ehT
,edisni gnidils tfahs ehT
.ralloc ruoy ssorca edilg eugnot tfos taht tel dna
,os gniod dna elkcuhc mih gniraeH
.desucof hsitef ot naelC
.mrah yna esuac ton did yeht tub
.retteb hcum tlef taerter eht dna