.hguone dias reh tfel d'eh gum ehT
,tsehc taerg reh ni peed demmuh ehS
,spets reh denetsah neht dna
iluaP secnarF yb
.esaet eht yawa evag seye sih ni tnilg eht tub
seye reH .delbmum hsiT ”,t'ndluoc ylekiL“
mih evigrof dluow sraL fi
”.gniht eno rof ,gniyd m'I“ ”?ton yhW“
”.tluaf ruoy s'ti ,ereht teg ew erofeb eid I fI .hsiT m'I“
.raeb sih htiw deneppah dah tahw dna
.dluoc eh sa raf sa drawrof denael dna
.retsaf liat sih devaw dna
evah thgim ti naht ssel deyaws ydob reH
,sgel reh fo tuo stonk eht dekrow dah gniklaw eht tub
pac eht denrutpu eH
,enut das a deyalp tekcirc a ,ecnatsid eht nI
.dehcterts ylreporp tlef selcsum reh dna
.seye s'xof eht ni erad a saw ereht tuB
.erahs ot detnaw eh ,gnihtyna fi ,hcum woh ediced ot mih gniwolla ,teiuq tpek ehS
,doownrohT dnuora sdleif eht dettod shtnicayh dna sesucorC
,pot somreht sih dewercsnu xof ehT
toof talf eno detfil ehS
,won reh ekat dluow peels yranidro ylnO
elzzum reh otni seirreb teews fo lufdnah a deffuts hsiT
,ssenisword retniw reh ffo nekahs tsuj ylno d'ehS
.nips lanif eht no tib a delbmuf teef reh dna nwod emac smra reH
,enips reh ni kcirc eht ot eud
.yrots sih dellats dah romuh riehT
”.yenoh eht teg ew retfA“
”.yadot eid ot tnaem I“
,etam reh fo smaerd
,oot ,teiuq neeb d'eH
.dewehc ehs elihw detnurg dna
.denediw seye s'xof ehT
”,raeb a gnitad ysae ton s'tI“
,swalc suolucitem htiw ruf reh debmoc ehS
pu dekrep dlanoR
doownrohT drawot nirg sih detniop xof ehT
”.eeffoc lufthgiled a werb yehT“
.noitisop gnittis a otni flesreh devaeh ehS ”?tahw rednow uoY“
”.ni em od ot dnuob si dnuorg dloc eht no gnipeelS“
.emit gnol yrev a rof gnihtyna ni detseretni neeb t'ndah ehs dnA
.taert a rof ni saw dlanoR
.sknird rieht rof gnol tiaw ot evah t'ndid yeht os
,senituor yliad rieht nageb slamina sa
”.uoy knaht ,eeffoc etauqeda tuB“
.mih ta deralg hsiT
.ria gnirps mraw eht hguorht meht gnivaw
”.ypmurg elttil a pu ekaw lla ew esoppus I“
.noitseuq a etiuq t'nsaw tI
neht dna wap eno htiw meht dettap ylno raeb dlo eht
.eulb tselap dna knip
ngis desolc erauqs eht saw
”.gniht emas eht yas ot desu sraL“ ”.ylerab tsuj tuB“
.ssarg eht dehcaer t'ndah tub spoteert eht til nus ehT
,ylerus ,gniyarg saw ruf reH
redluohs eno htiw mih degdun hsiT
,dnoces a rof tsuj
elttil a dehcterts dlanoR
,raeb a saw ehs tub ,dlo saw ehS
.sdeen s'xof a rof gib oot raf saw tI
ytterp saw sraL“ ”?eb enoyreve lliW
,gnirps ni skeew wef a rof demoolb ylno srewolfdliw ehT
.ydob derit reh hguorht gnirettulf llits selgnit ytnim eht rof hsrah oot ,eciov elam a saw tI
,ti edih ot deirt eH
,tneidebosid dna yriw enog dah sriah yarg eht erehW
.ynapmoc taerg dna eeffoc doog ekil
doownrohT ni eeffoc ehT
.meht neewteb ria eht gniffins ,reh ta detniuqs eH
htooms eb ot dedeen ti erehw ti gnihtooms
.htrow ’sraey owt—
”.gninrom eht ni uoy ees ll'I“ ”?haeY“
.ratcen kciht dna ssarg hserF
.reh detpurretni eciov hsarb a
.reh ediseb dehcram dlanoR ”.oS“
.seye reh gnisolc ,delworg hsiT ”,yawa oG“
,enot sih ta delims ehS
”,dlanoR si eman yM“
tops hgih a ,dleif eht fo retnec eht ot
.ni gnilttes enoemos fo
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.dias dlanoR ”,uoy rof dooG“
.ediw smra reh gnihcterts dna
.dnim t’ndid ehs tub
”?yltcaxe gniod ysub er'uoy taht ti si tahW
.tekcaj neerg sih denethgiarts dna
”,yrp ot tnaw t'nod I“
,gninrom eht fo tsom rof teiuq neeb dah dlanoR ”.doog sllemS“
”?llew sa doof evres yeht od dnA“
.eno lufepoh a tub ,gnos suovren a—
.taht rof sgnits wef a naht erom nekat d'eH
.ti no detniap seisiad htiw rood wolley ytterp a dna
.snoitacilbuP laoG yb dehsilbup dnirG yliaD ehT ni deraeppa tsrif yrots sihT .iluaP secnarF
”,enobkcab ym tsniaga gnibbur si hcamots yM“
.ti otni eeffoc ruop ot nugeb ydaerla d'eh ,rewsna dluoc ehs erofeB
sreh fo pot eht revo detaolf tI
.dias xof eht ”,sey hO“
.htaerb reh denethgil dah ria hserf ehT
.dias ehs ”,gniyd m'I“
.seye reh desolc raeb gniyarg ehT
.meht dednuorrus gnirps fo stnecs eht
”.thgir eht no nwod kcolb a tsuj s'tI“
.tnemom a rof rehtona eno ta derats yehT
.eromyna lla ta ehca t'ndid kcab reh tub
edis eno ot daeh sih detlit eH
”.si ti ,seY“ ”.ti rof yad eciN“
tifeneb s'xof eht rof sdnah reh pu werht ehS ”?ton yhw
”.eno hguot a s'tahT“
.tekcaj neerg enif a htaeneb morf tuo gnikeep
”.eeffoc eht evah ew retfa tae ot emoclew er'uoy ,lleW“ .dias eh
”.sdrawretfa eid ot emit fo ytnelp evah dluohs uoY
.dias hsiT ”,t'nod nehT“
.ereht ytirucesni fo tnih eht dna romuh eht ta
,sbuc ym desiar ,efil ym devil ev'I“
”?eeffoc retteb evah uoy did erehW“ ”?tahW“
”.pu ekow eh nehw ereht eb d'uoy thguoht eh ebyaM“
.reh ees dluoc eh ton ro rehtehw
,gnihton saw ti tub
.slevel ygrene sih htiw pleh yna dedeen xof der elttil eht enigami t'ndid ehs hguoht ,dias hsiT
.yenoh dna gnirps dna seeb fo ecnad eht
”.nepo t'nsi pohs ruoY“
.noissefnoc sih deredisnoc ehs elihw yenoh eht ta dekcus dna
.raey tsrif eht yako saw tI“
.meht ees ot nwot ssorca kert eht ekam ot
.lla retfa aedi doog a hcus t'nsaw gniyd ekil tlef ehS
,mih ta delworg ehS
,gnibmob-evid dna gnizzub deppots yllanif dah seeb eht ,daehrevO
,nwot fo edistuo sdleif eht ni srewolf fo ytnelp erew erehT
”.rebmemer nac I naht regnol ni yenoh hserf dah t'nevah I“
,etihw dna elprup
.kcab gnimoc t'nsaw eh wonk ot ria eht ffins ot deen t'ndid ehS
.worromot syawla saw ereht tuB
.srae dna seye sih denetfos noisserpxe luftsiw A
.esolc seye reh tel dna
.dluow yeht tahw eb meht tel
.pirt elohw eht rof ecap rewols reh dehctam dah eH
,tnemom teiuq ,gnol a retfA
,rohtua noitcif yrruf gninniw-drawa yb ”worromoT syawlA“
daehrevo seeb eht dna ,delkcuhc eH
”?hsats terces ruoy hctef ot yad elohw a su ekat ti lliW
.meht no tsol saw rewop sti tub
emit gnol a neeb dah tI
.moc.iluapsecnarf ta
”.sgnits eht htrow ylniatrec saw tI“
.eil eht ta delbmur ylleb s'hsiT ”.yrgnuh ton m'I“
:sedis lla ot tuo deyalps srewolf eht erehw
.tcaf ni ,oga gnol oot ton
.yrneH htiw etad a no eeffoc doownrohT eht deirt tsrif d'ehS
?siht teg uoy did erehW“
,dleif wolley rieht morf delims seisiad detniap ehT
rood eht nepo dellup raeb dlo eht dna
.seiromem nwo rieht ni tsol htob
goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,yllej ot denrut selcsum reh yaw eht
emit doog a dah eW“
tnurg deifsitas a htiw dewollaws ehS
”.ylzzirg a saw eH“ .nageb dlanoR
,thgilnus eht htiw enohs seye s'xof ehT
gum eht hsiT dessap eH ”.deednI“ ”?ton yhW“
,tfos eciov reh tpek ehS
.liat sih fo gnihsiws yrrem eht ni egnellahc A
.wodniw eht ni gnignah
,deddon hsiT ”.sih saw gum ehT
”.edurtni ot naem t'nod I“
,niaga tae reven dluow ti ekil doof devarc ydob reh yaw eht
.pets driht yreve reh htiw ecnad ti no srewolf eht gnikam
.sedirts ruof doog a yb xof eht gnitaeb dna
.yaw eht gnola sthgis eht ni pu thguac neeb htob d'yeht spahreP
.yrwa striks reh htiw dnuorg eht ot gnirettulf
.wonk uoy ,tops terces ruO
”.semitemos dnuorg eht no peels ot sdeen raeb A“
.ekowa ehs nehw enog saw dlanoR
”?sraL ruoy saw oga gnol woH“
.eye reh fo renroc eht fo tuo ria eht gniffins xof eht thguac hsiT tub
,gij yppah a decnad xof ehT
,niaga ekops eh nehw ypeels dednuos eciov siH
,seot sih htiw dnuorg eht hcaer ot
.rehgih elzzum reh detfil dna
.raeb a eb ot saw ti tahw derebmemer tsuj ylno d'ehs erehw tsehc reh ni peed ,delkcuhc dna seye reh desolc hsiT ”.lleW“
”.os eveileb t'nod I“
.tpels d'eh erehw tops eht ni detiaw
ytineres teiuq a otni llef elbat eht tub
”.doownrohT ot og t'nac I“
,mih ecaf ot dellor hsiT
.flesreh top a ekam ot hguone ekawa neeb d'ehs ecnis
,swodniw eht ni sthgil htiw sesuoh elttiL
.niaga elzzum sih ot ylwols ti gnitfil ,ti gnisserac
,srewolf fo tnecs eht delahni ehs ,yadoT
”?em tbuod uoy diD“
”worromoT syawlA“ saw sihT
,gnitfihs mih draeh hsiT
”.mmh-mM“ ”.kcab gnillup ,suovren
.delbbow selcsum reh dna truh enips reH
.nus eht sa yreehc dna thgirb
.ngis eht ta derats hsiT ”.tarD“
.deregnil noisnet tub
,pohs eeffoc eht dehcaorppa yeht sA
,ffo detfird ,dexaler d'ehS
reh ta deknilb eH ”.ees I“
?reh tuoba gniklat eh saw ro
.gnitsud dedeen ylbaborp ti dna yenoh rof raj yalc ylevol a dah ehS .retal rof emos evas dluohs ehs tub ,suoicileD
”.niaga gnivom tog yllanif eh nehw noinuer taerg taht saw ereht tub ,esruoc fo ,ylenol tog I
.somreht a tuo dellup dna
pu evig ot ecalp a ecin sa saw
.deddon dna kcab tas eH ”.hO“ ”.eruS“ .yna sa
,tnorf eht gnola swodniw egral htiw
.dekrow dah ti thguoht ehs ,tnemom a roF
.tnew ti woh wonk ot dekil evah d'ehS
”.hpmH“ ”.fo gniyd si enoemos tahw rednow seod eno tuB“ .dias xof eht
.reh dellif revolc dna tnim fo stnecs eht dna ,decnad hsiT
.yltnatculer gum eht kcab mih dednah hsiT
somreht sih deitpme d'eh neht dna
,tfig s'dlanoR gniyrraC
,loots sih morf depmuj eH ”.on ,hO“
.daeh sih gnikahs ,yawyna kcab dekrej eh tub
.sgnidliub foor-dehctaht eht dennacs dna deffins ehS
egde s'wodaem eht ta deppots ehs ,yadoT
sdray worran ni gnipmor sbuc dna
.lla ta noisserpxe reh ees dluoc eh gnitbuod
,ruf reh htiw deyalp ezeerb ehT
.evih rieht ot enod dah hsiT egamad eht gniriaper fo krow eht ot kcab gniog
.denetfos eciov siH
.ti ot enihw hgih a dah hgual s'xof ehT
kcab daeh reh denael ehS ”.tcaf ni ,thgim I“
.dehctiwt eson reH
,ssenkrad eht ni dekcilc swalc siH
pohs elttil eht ot secap wef
,edis eht ot daeh sih denrut dna ffo deliart eH
.won reh dniheb saw siht fo lla—
,dah eb ot yenoh fo gnas ylleb reH
,hO“ .oot ,s'yrneH
.detfil dah knuf roprot-tsop reH
.uoy no nwod gnittuhs strats ydoB“
.knurt s'eert eht tsniaga kcab sih htiw tas dlanoR
”worromoT syawlA“   :yojne esaelP
.dehctiwt eson reH
,thgil gnidaf eht ni tas htob yehT
”.selkna eseht htiw ti ekam reven d'I
,wodaem eht otni deppets ehs nehW
eton dluoc ehs ecnereffid ylno ehT
,deracs tog I sseug I“
,sloots eht dnuora gniregnil eeffoc fo stnih eht llems llits dluoc ehS ”?ti si emit tahW“
.wollahs dna deggar erew shtaerb reH
.ssenkrad eht ni ria fo repsihw gnol a ,dehgis eH
,selbat klawedis eht gnola tes sthgieh suoirav fo sloots
.teef derit reh denoihsuc sneerg kciht eht
,reppus ot nwod gnittis seilimaf
.srae detniop sih ot ylraen daerps nirg s'xof ehT ”?ti t'nsi ,dooG“
.emoh daeh ylbaborp dluohs ehs
”.gninrom eht ni pu teg tsuj I nehw nialpmoc senob ym dna
.ria thgin eht deffins hsiT ”.desserpeD“
.deworran seye siH
.yks eulb a yb dekcab
gum dehtuom-ediw a decudorp dna niaga gab sih ni dehsif eH
,deklaw ehS .sgniht gniworg
.yad lanoitasrevnoc ,yranidro na otni denrut dah tI
”.yats ot thgif yltcaxe t'ndid eh dna
,raeb sih dnuof dah dlanoR fi derednow ehs ,deklaw ehs sA
.rehto eht ot toof eno morf decnad dna ,gniggaw liat
.enog saw roprot ehT .reh
,ffo erew sthgil eht tub
.htrof dna kcab liat sih deksihw dna
.eson yrehtael reh ni dednapxe slirtson s'hsiT
.seiromem nwo sih ot gniklat erew eh fi sa
.rehtegot gnippat
”.worromot syawla s'erehT“
,ssenffits tuohtiw emac spets reH
”,nwot fo edistuo tsuj hctap yrreb a saw erehT“
,nwod tnew nus eht litnu seirreb no degrog d'yehT
”.daeha thgir og uoY .on ,hO“
”.ylralucitrap toN“
”.neht ,og s'teL“ .oga
”.ti detsat ev'I ecnis elihw a neeB“
.dias ehs ”,emit s'tI“
,reh ta yltcerid detniop elzzum gnol siH
,sedirts ruof rehtona rof ylsseldeeh deunitnoc spetstoof ehT
,yllautneve meht rof gnikool og neve thgim ehS
,eid ot tnaem d'ehs taht derebmemer ,depsag ehS
”.no emoC“ .dias dlanoR
”?retteb dah ev'uoY“
.senots prahs ekil detnilg seye sih dna
.srats ni tuo nekorb dah yks eht ,daehrevO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ecnelis eht ekorb dlanoR
.yrekcom ro tnemtnioppasid neeb evah thgim taht enot a ot detfihs eciov siH
klaw eht fI“
.gnippis rieht fo sdnuos eht yb ylno nekorb
.raf taht ton s'tI“
.wap eno fo kcab eht htiw htuom reh depiw dna
.elzzum dezis-raeb a rof elbatius
,evom ot ygrene hcum toN
.daeh reh llif amora kciht eht gnittel
.eeffoc rof ni pord dluow raeb sih dna dlanoR ebyaM
.ot desu ehs naht retsaf derit ehs ,ylniatreC
,sragus nedlog fo gum eht ot deldnurt ,doots ehS
.tser fo yltnatsnoc demaerd dah ehs yaw eht
.taerg saw gnirps tahT“
,ecno raeb a htiw tnew I“
.nihc reh ediseb thgit sredluohs reh gnilruc enips reh
doownrohT derugif ehs dna
yarg si ruf yM .etam ym tsol
,yawa mih dehsup I
.rehto eht neht dna edis eno ot derettuts spets reh dna
”.setunim wef a evah I esoppus I“
?ti tfel uoy erehw eb gnihtyreve lliW
”?os kniht uoY“ ”.eugra enola tel
.knird reh hcaer ot ylthgils os reve dehcnuh hsiT elihw
.ecnart ecnad-tsop reh deliops dah gnirettan sih sa hcum sa wodaem eht tuo denword dah werb sih fo amora eht dna
.etats lamron sih ton saw taht niatrec tlef hsiT dna
,dehcnip llits kcen tuots reh fo esab eht ta evren ehT
,steerts trid eht otni dessorc dlanoR dna ehs nehw tuB
ekops xof eht dna
”.tae ot deen t'nod I“ .dias eh
ria eht ni gnignah taht tfel eH ”…rednow I“
.wollof ot esimed reh htiw etad a dna—
.erehwemos gnimoolb seilil erew erehT
”.yad ylevol a s'ti dnA“ .dedda ehs
,dah syawla ti sa yltcaxe dekool ecalp ehT
.ssarg eht no gnignuol eniltuo s'dlanoR tuo ekam llits dluoc ehs tub
dnuorg eht no thgin ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.ot tnaw I fi eid ot hguone dlo m'I“
snosaes ynam oS
edis eht ot dellor ylno ehs ,dne eht nI
,meht erofeb sgum gnimaets owt htiW
spil reh ot gum eht desserp hsiT
,shtaerb nezod a retfA .gnikniht
.sraeb tuoba tib a wonk did yllaer dlanoR
.sega ni dah ehs naht retteb tlef ehs ,tcaf nI
.detinuer yeht fI
reh deksa tsrif dah yrneH erehw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.deneppah tahw tuo dnif
.kert eht otni ruoh doog a gnippop deppots dah seenk reh dna
noissefnoc taht ni ynoga saw erehT ”.llaf tsaL“
.tnew ehs sa tnargarf werg ria ehT
”?melborp eht s'tahw ,uoy sllik
.gnippis sih ot denruter dna
,niaga tnelis llef yehT ”.haey hO“
.meht dnuora srewolf eht gnitcelfer
,dehsinav tub lla dah kcen reh ni niap eht ,tcaf nI
.lleweraf regae na reh gnignis seeb eht htiw ffo dedaeh hsiT
.eert eht htaeneb edis sih no yal eh taht os detfihs dna dehgis eH
.dnuora dekool dna rellat tas hsiT
”?eb lliw raeb roprot-tsop a esoppus uoy od gnivigrof woH“
,sgnits htiw nellows eson roop sih gninigami ,delims hsiT
.noos meht ees d'ehs ebyaM
.sbuc evah ot detnaw ehs fi
redluohs eno revo kcab gab sih deggurhs xof ehT ”?oS“
tsud eht ni deggard liat siH .depoord xof ehT
.tis ot deirt dna seye reh denepo hsiT
”.togrof tsomla I .hA“
.seeb dna gnicnad morf no devom dah yad ehT
.dlanoR ,wonk reven uoY“
,ygrene eht dah ro ,egru eht tlef d'ehs ecnis sraey gnol eerht neeb dah ti dna
.mih ta deknilb hsiT
stnecs wodaem ycips eht gnirewoprevo
.denruter nirg sih dna ,won dekrep srae sih tub
.hgis luftsiw a evag dlanoR
.ekawa dekrej ehS ”?hsiT …luftbuoD“
.yawa dessap yrneH reh ecnis dah ti naht retsaf taeb traeh reh dna
.ecnad gnol a ton saw tI
.edisni morf gnitfaw stnecs hcir eht delahni dna
.yenoh hserf detsat d'ehs ecnis emit gnol a neeb dah tI
meht dnuora deltsub nwot ehT
,ykcul saw ehs fi ,dna
.htaed rof flesreh deraperp dna
htuom reh ni sregnif reh kcuts hsiT ”.seY“
.tsud ot esuoh a dah ehs yadoT .ebyaM
.rehtie raeb eht no ysae ton s'ti tuB“
.ti htiw tnew sniap dna sehca reh fo tsal ehT
.pohs eht fo thgis ni erew yeht erofeb meht dehcaer amora eeffoc ehT # ”.wonk reven uoY
# ”.hcamots ytpme na no eid ot emahs a eb dluow tI“
.ecnalg syawedis a htiw hsiT deye dna
.drawrof dekrep srae ralugnairt owT
,smra htob desiar ehs dna
,nwo sti fo cigam a dah gnihguaL
.amora eeffoc ydaeh eht delahni yllatnedicca dna detrons hsiT
.roprot reh fo tsal eht yawa mraw nus eht tel hsiT
,triks reh htaeneb dehctiwt liat reH
.seiceps roprot-non a htiw pihsnoitaler a eusrup ot raeb a rof ysae t'nsaw tI
”.dlanoR ,uoy knahT“
”.hsiT ,sknahT“ .elbidua ylerab
”.worromot syawla s'erehT“
sraL sih tuoba deirrow dlanoR saw tub
,gniklat tuohtiw doownrohT fo tuo gnitfird ,efac eht tfel yehT
.srewolf fo dleif a ni ylteiuq no gnissap naht tnereffid laed taerg a saw noitsuahxe fo gniyd taht reh dlot cigol reH
.oga syad owt denigami d'ehs sa dlo os ton saw ehs tub
dlanoR ni detseretni
.eeffoc krad fo erusaem a deruop dna
.ssarg eht hguorht dedaerht wap siH
.ssarg eht ni deggel-ssorc tas xof A
”.regnol elttil a tiaw dluoc gniyd esoppus I“ ”.raf ton s'tI“
.od ot sgniht dah ehs dna
evorp ot gnihtemos dah ehs derebmemer hsiT ,woN
,reh deyarteb ylleb reh tub
”.shtnom wef a rof tuoba kluks tsuj d'I dna pan d'eh ,wonk uoY
.thgir eht neht dna tfel eht ot deppets dna
.puc dezis-raeb eht morf spord tsal eht deniard dna
.hguone noos dne t'ndluoc taht nrub eht ta gnibburcs swap tevlev sih
eldarc ssarg eht tel dna dehgis ehS
.nialpmoc t'ndid senob reh taht dnuorg hguone tfos htiw tekciht a dnuof dah dlanoR tub
kcab reh otno gnillor ,dias ehs
,htrae eht ot llihc a saw erehT
savnac eht otni sregnif kcalb sih kcuts eh daetsni tub ,og dna ti eveirter ot mih delliw ehS
,srewolf eht dima decnad ehS
”.emit thgir eht s'tI“
”.yawa rehtraf llup d'eh dna thgif a kcip d'I .ytsan neht
.seye reh otni gnikael ti leef dluoc ehs hguoht
gum ytpme reh nwod tes hsiT
.mih ediseb dnuorg eht no deppord d'eh kcas neerg eht rof dehcaer dna deddon xof ehT
.klaw s'yad-flah a s'doownrohT
.eson gnibborht reh tsniaga swap htob debbur ehS
,ssarg eht hguorht delffir ezeerb A .gnitegdif
.ti otni eugnot reh deppid dna
.dehgis raeb dlo eht dna
.denway dna yltnesba ruf reh ta dehctircs ehS
.pu ekow ylleb s'hsiT ”?yenoH“
,ria eht ot ecips a dedda
.sedis eht ot llef srae sih dna
ecnartne efac eht ot gniyrruh
,eromyna eid ot tnaw t'ndid ehs ecniS
,eugnot reh denrub eeffoc toh ehT .knard dna
”.eeffoc eht tuoba thgir eb tsuj thgim uoY“
.eeffoc doog yrev si sihT“
# .striks reh htaeneb dehctiwt liat ybbuts reh dna ,gnarps spets reH
,esnet tog sgnihT“
si yrots s’yadot dna
srats eht ta delims ehS ”.od I“
tsal eht depmats ehS .hcihw llet t’ndluoc ehS
.werb gnimaets eht deppis dna
.stneserp ecitsloS sih gnitiawa buc a ekil
”.klaw a esu dluoc I dnA“ .dias xof eht
.deb reh fo tam pmad a edam weD
,dekool eh dna ssarg eht tsniaga deksihw liat s'xof ehT
,mih ta ssorca detniuqs dna thgilnoom eht otni gum ediw eht detfil hsiT
,iluaP secnarF yb
”,esle gnihtemos saw tahT“ .gnitiaw
swodaem eht ot klaw eht no denialpmoc seenk reH
,ruf reh hguorht dehcael ti dna
”?roprot s'nosaes siht naem uoY“
,seert eht evoba detfil nus ehT
.niaga srae s'dlanoR esiar ot hguone ylduol gnilbmurg
,tuo reh thguos d'eH
,yaw eht gnola llA
.dlanoR ediseb nwot fo egde eht ot derettot hsiT emit eht yb seert rif eht fo spot eht woleb deppid dah nus ehT
.enips reh gninethgiarts ,kcab sredluohs reh dehsup dna ylpeed dehtaerb hsiT
.srats eht ta delims hsiT ”.xes pu-ekaW“
.etirovaf reh neeb syawla dah
”,gnihtemos tae ot emiT“
krow s'secnarF tuoba erom tuo dnif nac uoY
.eciov reh fo tuo tnemeticxe eht peek ot deirt dna
.thginot rO“ .detrons hsiT
.roprot retniw diugnal ,peed eht ekil lla ta gnihton
,yks eht ta derats dna srewolf eht gnoma kcab yal neht dna
.gnivil ot kcab noitnetta reh werd wodaem eht tsniaga teef fo gniltsur ehT
,retsaf elttil a dehcram hsiT
.moolb yks eht hctaw ot kcab yal dna gum eht nwod tes ehs dna
”.doownrohT ni pohs elttil a s'erehT“ .dehgis hsiT
,hserf fo llems eht htiw dellif ria delahni ylirgnuh ehS
.ti ni t'nsaw traeh reh tub
.srewolf ni derevoc triks a erow hsiT
.teef reh ot kcab gnibmilc fo ssecorp suoudra eht nageb neht dna
.delttes erew ti fi sa gab sih gnikcaper nageb dna teef sih ot deppop xof ehT
”…tsuj s'tI .thgir ,thgiR“
.shtnom retniw gnol eht rof ynapmoc sevlesmeht peek ot dah rentrap evitca eht dna
.reh dellik t'ndah
.tpels uoy elihw deneppah tahw gnirednow pu ekaw uoy raey yrevE .tol a ssim uoY
.sregnif reh morf yenoh fo sgerd eht kcil ot tnemom a gnikat dna mra eno htiw pu flesreh gnipporp
,suoiruc flesreh dnuof hsiT
dehgis ehS ”.yltnecer toN“
”?dah eb ot eeffoc suolucarim siht si erehW“
”?ton yhW .eid ot yad enif a si yadoT“
.selbat dezis-muidem eht fo eno ta tas yeht
.ylgnisucca demaets eeffoc sih dna
,gum sih revo tfird swap sih dehctaw ehS
”?gum eht tuoba em llet ot gniog uoY“
.won yb roprot fo tuo eb dluow sraL sih dnA
.pu ti thguorb d'eh tub ,ssenisub reh t'nsaw tI
,nus gninrom eht ni demaelg tlep yddur siH
sdap reh htaeneb dehsurc sbreh ehT
,hcum os no tuo dessim raeb ehT
”.ti wonk uoY“ ”.yxeS .hA“
# ”.taht htiw evil nac I kniht I“
”.ti ekil gnihtyna nees reven ev'I“
.swap reh ni gum eht denrut dna
,meht tel tsuj raeb gib eht dna ,tuo evag seenk reh ,dehsinif ehs sA
.yffulf eb ot dedeen ti erehw ti gniffulf dna
,gniht laer a saw noisserped roprot-tsoP
.detcepsus ehs sa ylisae sa
.ti tuoba teiuq tpek seenk reh dna
”?yenoh emos teg ew retfA“
.dias ehs ”,dnim t'nod uoy fI“
,segde eht ta eulb dna tfos nworg dah thgin ehT
,enips reh htaeneb looc tlef dnuorg ehT
”?neht ,gniyd llitS“
.niaga deddon hsiT ”.hA“
.enola tiaw gnol rehtona ot daeha gnikool
”.nwo sih no hctef nac xof a gnihtemos ton s'ti tuB
.ereh morf raf ton yenoh tcelloc ot desu I dna sraL“
.derrulb srewolf eht litnu daeh reh koohs ehS
,eid ot desoppus saw ehs yad eht nO
,sediseB .t'ndid I ,lleW“
,roprot tsrif reh derebmemer ehs dna ,reh ta nwod delkniwt srats ehT
.gnilgnit selcsum reh tlef hsiT dna
gnitteg detrats I ,dnuora dellor llaf nehw tuB .doog saw remmuS
,elzzum reh ot eeffoc eht detfil ehS
,seeffoc rieht fo flah doog a denwod d'yeht nehW
.rehtegot swap tevlev sih deppalc eH ”.suolevraM“
,rehto eht retfa pets tneitap eno
dnuos tcnitsid eht draeh ehs hcihw retfa
”.enod m'I dna eeffoc doog fo puc a tsuJ“
,ecnad ylevol a hcus saw ti tuB“ ”.ysub m'I“
”.mih gnirb uoy yenoh hcum woh no dneped lliw taht esoppus I“
”.sraeb tuoba lla wonk uoy esoppus I“
.eeffoc fo gum rehtona htob meht gniruop
,htap netaeb eht gnola yltneitap dna ylwols tnew ehS
#    .yenoh tseteews fo lluf ylleb a dna ,sbuc reh
”.pu ekow eh retfa thgir desserped
.nwot fo dne raf eht drawot gnirats
”,eeffoc fo puc laer a dnA“
ti gniknird fo trohs tsuj desuap eh tub
.woble na no pu flesreh depporp dna
,seeb fo gnos eht ot denetsil
.gniht retniw eht hguorht teg dluoc ew thguoht I“ ”?tuB“
…dna tsap gniklaw eb ot deneppah I dna
yenoh htiw gnimmirb puc dezis-raeb A
.nruter ssenivaeh reh tlef hsiT
”…dneirf doog a ,nuf fo tol a saw sraL
”,eludehcs eht no esle gnihtyna evah t'noD“ ”.ees I“
”?yadot gniyd no nalp llits uoy oD
.edisni devom gnihton dna
”.eeffoc eht naht retteb saw yenoh eht kniht I“
,elzzum sih ot knird eht detfil swap ytevleV
,hsur gninrom eht fo sleeh eht no devirra d'yehT
,elims nwo reh kcab dleh hsiT
.rehtie ,liat yhsub taht fo gniggaw suoixna eht gnikatsim on saw erehT
.seenk reh morf lla ta tnemugra yna tuohtiw denehtgnel sedirts s'hsiT
”?uoy t'nod ,mih ssim uoY“
.swap reh no kcab denael dna dennirg hsiT
,ydaets dleh eciov siH ”.sey ,hO“
.amora yttun ,kciht a htiw
”.pmacs ,seY“
.dehgis dna ydob reh dnuora swap reh depparw hsiT
”?erehW“ ”—elttil ytniop ruoy rof gib oot raf s'tI
.ti snialpxe taht ,lleW“
.ydob yriah reh koohs elkcuhc wol A ”.ebyaM“
.edis sih ta gnola delffuhs dna dennirg ehS
.gninraw a dezzub
.tsehc reh ni eton das a tup yrots sih dna ,yvaeh nworg dah
.raeb a saw ehs esuaceb yllacificeps ,spahrep
”?emos ekil uoy dluoW“ ”?tahW“ ”?eeffoC
.emahs fo hcuot a dna
”?deneppah tahw oS“
.tuo dehcterts sgel reh dna