,ytisrevinu eht ta sessalc sih gnirud mih ot deneppah tahw morf emac seirots tseb
noisiced ym ,llitS
.reilrae ruoh na emoh gnimoc no
dna…syadawon gnihtyna yas lliw slarebil ,wonk I ,wonk I
,llaM lanoitaN eht ssorca setis cirotsih ees ot snoitidepxe gnineve no tnew stsiruoT
,dehserfer teg uoy ,yawynA“ ”.yas t’nac…“
”?eciffo eht ta yad gnoL“
”,kcirp cibohpomoh ,thgitpu na s’edud eht esuaceb s’taht llew ,haeY“ ”.ssob ym ro
enileeb a edam I ,)niaga(
.tniopefink ta deggum
,dewols taebtraeh yM .yltaerg
?nac uoy sa tsaf sa ereht em teg uoy naC“ ,deksa neht
”,taht dedeen I ,sknahT“
,nosnhoJ htiw gnikrow detrats I retfA“
nam gnuoy a dna nooccar tluda na sa
,ereht gnorw ton
dna tekcaj ym otni em depleh neht ohw
”?yrrow ot em tnaw
”.ffo worromot dna thginot tog ev’I tsael tA“
.egairram naeporuE rieht etarbelec ot madretsmA morf dnabsuh sih thguorb
”!owt uoy
.decafruser reve recnac s’yenraB fi latipsoh a ot sthgir noitatisiv em gniwolla sa llew sa ,ylimaf
uoY“	         .sdrow sih deohce I
.ecneitap ym detset nosnhoJ litnu dnim ym pu ekam t’ndid I
.em otni efil fo gninaem eht dehtaerb negyxo sih fi sa mih dessik I
.kcab eht ni selttob elpuoc a evah dluohs I“
”?wonk’y ,deyonna sa eb ton d’I dna ,evitanigami eb tsael tA
,sreppordsevae morf skool ytrid gnitteg elihw scipot niatrec dnuora gnicnad gnituo hcae dneps ot tnaw t’ndid tub
,su rof dleh erutuf eht revetahW
,ereh owt uoy ees ot tcepxe t’ndid I“
.rewohs taht ekat og ot em dellepmoc hcamots ym ni lworg wol A
.pord elgnis a toN
.evol ni gnieb rof em hsinup depleh revetahW
.tuons ym pu tperc elims llams A
?emit siht tae ot tuo og
,ti morf nrael t’nod ew fi dab ylno si egnahc tahT
ecnO	         .gnidliuB lotipaC eht fo spets tnorf eht nwod deklaw I sa esactius ym debbarg I ,nehT
.saxeT .V ecnerwaL fo esac eht ecnis
”?reffats elttil doog a eb tsuj ro em llet ot gniog uoy erA“
I“	         .eno otni pu dellor llA .rehtaf detpoda dna
,od annaw uoy tahw tuo erugif ot uoy rof emit fo ytnelP
regnol on I taht
dehcaorppa neve t’ndah I
*** ”.taht yas nac uoY“
ekil sgniht gnitseretni rehto sa llew sa ,taht ees ylraelc dluow sdrocer cilbup ruo fo hcae detagitsevni ohw ydobynA
.sessalg detnit-esor hguorht .C.D fo tser eht deweiv
?siht si ohw ,olleH“
”.yenraB ,oot uoy evol
,evaw gnihsarc a fo
.qarI fo noisavni gniogno eht fo sretsetorp gninmednoc hceeps laitnetop a etirw I detsisni
srekrow fo detsisnoc yltsom shtoob egatniv eht ni reppus rof nwod gnittis esoht ,devirra ew
.sih no sregnif ym gnitser ,gul gib eht ot deifiralc I
”.yrros os m’I dna etal m’I wonk I“
,rettal eht gnieb em tuoba kcarcesiw a sekam neht eH
ro tuoyal roiretni eht rof noitaroda ti llaC
.moor gnivil detcennoc eht otni
elbat eht no swoble ym detser neht
I“	         ”?uoy htiw yrgna eb I dluohs yhw
seirf hcnerF fo daetsni dalas a evah I naC“
rehgih eht rehtob t’now ti ,stneduts eht gnihcaet peek dna boj ym od I sa gnol sA .erac
sicoV sumoD yb
retsinab gnidnecsed eht revo dereep I
,semoh rieht ot gniriter
”,swen eht no tuoba gniklat s’ydobyna lla s’ti ecnis ,mmH“ ”.krow tuoba hcum
.saxeT .v ecnerwaL gnidulcni
.boj ym gniod fo sruoh retfa
t’ndid I fi prewt eht no gnittih emit ym lla tneps I gniyas yddad reywal sih ot og d’eh gniyas
,nettogrof gnieb ksir eseht
lanoitutitsnocnu deralced llA
,)dnuora nosnhoJ .peR gniwollof elihw ni tas netfo I sriahc elbatrofmocnu eht ot derapmoc(
”nwonK reveN tuB ,neeS syawlA“
.8102 ni
ylohcnalem leef em edam bac gnivom eht tsap rulb klawedis eht gnihctaW
,dias uoy ekil s’tI“ .em dlot eH
ytefas ym rof derac dna devol yenraB esuaceB
.derettam esle gnihtoN
”?yenraB“	         .edis ym yb yenraB htiw eb syawla dluow ti wenk I ,t’ndid
.doolb fo pord eno erahs t’ndid I dna yenraB
,detartsurf eb d’uoy thguoht tsuj I“
?sgniht fo dne eht s’ti ekil tcaer ew fi ro
,elggig erutammi na selfits yenraB
.tsrif ta em decnivnoc tahw erew sngis rallod ehT
,nwod gnippirts hguorht yawdim esuap em edam
levon sih daer mih gnihctaw
”,uoy evol I wonk
.kcartaoc ybraen eht morf enim gnihctans dna tekcaj gnineve sih no gnittup
eb ot etunim eno deludehcs gniteem a eriuqer ,etunim tsal eht ta hceeps a fo sliated egnahc thgim reyolpme eht ,mihw a nO
,spoort eht gnitroppus nerdlihc tuoba yrots doog-leef a
.nairarbil a ekil kool mih edam dias netfo I dnik emas eht erew yehT
I“	         .unem a yenraB dednah ymmoT sa
.dessap ecnis gnol syad esoht rof
d’I tfard lanif eht fi no rednop roN
,hgU“ ”!nos ,neht doog sdnuoS“
ynam dna ,emit tsrif ruo gnirud ekil em deldarc eH
”,niaga deirrow em evah t’ndluohs uoY“
,ffo syad sih no detfarc sgnitniap hcstik yllufthgiled htiw sllaw eht gnitaroced devol yenraB hcum woh
ehT	         ”.krowrepap rieht gnilif ro selbat rieht gnitiaw er’ew fi
.dias enilef suoretsiob eht ”,esruoc fo
.suoires saw I fi gniees
,noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif osla nac uoY
,yrram ot selpuoc yag gniwolla aciremA ni etats on htiW
nalp did I ,hturt nI
”.ruoh artxe na yats I detsisni ssob nmad ehT
lacitiloP“	         ”.ssalc ym evael ot mih llet I dna
,gnilahxe dna gnilahnI
.revres dnoces a eb ot emit eht gnikat osla elihw selbat gnitiaw ni detsissa flesmih ymmoT ,ecivres tsedom a gniruD
.em dnuora dnaw sih evaw mih tel yltneitap ,draug ytiruces enilef eht ot egdab s’reffats lanoissergnoc ym dehsalf I
thgilnus fo syar gniyd eht sa wodniw edis tfel eht tuo dezag seye yM
,spil eht no mih kcep ot
,neercs noisivelet eht dna
”?emoh gniyats ew t’nerA“
,stneduts ruoy ot ereht dna ereh
,deksa eh ”,nairB ,oS“
naicitilop lufsseccus oN
.renemhöB fo selttob ruo ot txen ,elbat eht no gnitser yal ti sa wap ym dettap yenraB
.em ot unem eht dednah yenraB
,monev gnihtaol fo egniwt a htiw ,eb dluow rewsna ylno s’ymmoT ,tsom eht rof deretac eh ohw deksa reve ydobyna fI
”.yenraB ,epyt gnivigrof eht m’I ykcul os er’uoY
,seires yrots naipotsyd yrruf gniogno sih sedulcni hcihw
,sreerac egnahc ot tnaw uoy fI“
,rood ecnartne eht kcolnu ot pu deklaw I ,liat yhsub ym fo hsiws deiraew a htiW
.ffo evord eh erofeb god eht ot deddon I ”.sknahT“
.ksam nooccar sih dniheb em ta gnilims yltfos ,em dlot eh
”.moT ,koob dlo na ekil em wonk
.ni dekcik gnithgil teerts cigetarts eht dna
,sesac gnimocpu s’truoC emerpuS eht tuoba rednimer a yb dewollof
gniraeppa trihs dialp a dna snaej ni nooccar redlo ,rellat a ot del
derettam taht lla dna
,’ecalP s’ymmoT‘ no dediced eW	         *** ”.gniog teg s’teL“
!gnol oot neeb s’ti ,giarC
.meht ot gniretac elihw tesolc eht ni deniamer ew taht saw
,tahw rettam on em troppus dluow yenraB taht flesym gnicnivnoc neht
”?huh ,krans rof ecalp a evah t’nseod ecneicS
ton tub ,eruS ?egnahc nedduS
ll’I…hU“	         ”?irB ,uoy tuoba tahW“
,dab ro rehtaew doog
”?thginot gniog uoy stuob-a-erehW“
na gnimoceb em fo kniht uoy od tahW“	         ”?irB ,haeY“ ,tuhs levon eht gnisolc erofeb egap sih kramkoob ot regnif a desu eH	         ”?yenraB ,yeH“	         .edisni
.taorht s’yenraB fo kcab eht depacse elkcuhc dwel A ”.ereht em tog uoy
nevE“	         ”.tsixe ew kniht neve t’nod yeht ,emit eht fo tsoM
”.yenraB ,gniht eruS“
.su rof ylippah dellirt ymmoT
,yenraB“	         .pu denetfos elims decrof sih ,su fo thgis thguac regit eht dna ,ni deppets ew tnatsni ehT
.erom hcum dna rehtaf detpoda ym sA
”,sraey neves rehtona
dna sknurt miws ruo ylno gniraew
,hguorht og ot regnol koot ytiruces tropriA .syaw ynam os
.seiceps gnihctam fo smret ni saw
,hcaeB eltryM ot nwod pirt yrasrevinna htfif
,nooccar gnilggig eht ot tuo taps I ”,yddad ,ma eruS“
.roolf dnoces eht ot gnidael esacriats worran eht pu gniklaw detrats I sa em desitsahc eh
,koob txen sih gnidaer ot kcab tnew yenraB
uoY“	         ”?niaga kaets niolris eht rof gniog er’uoy ti ekat
,oot gnihtolc thgin lausac ni desserd yenraB dnif ot
ehT	         ”.esaelp ,yaw siht thgir ,yaw siht thgiR“
,elcriC tnopuD raen gnitser
”?sraey neves retfa rentrap ruoy morf tsrow eht tcepxe t’ndluohs uoy taht dnA
dluoW“	         ”—yllacinhcet I dna uoy
.sreyolpme tsap ym fo lla emalb t’ndluoc I ,senecs eht dniheb erew netfo sreyolpme ym
nekcihc ym fo lluf etib a no dewehc ydaerla I ,elihwnaeM .retal rof
,detrawht gnieb tolp tsirorret tsetal eht tuoba gniklat deppots reven swen eht
”,dnatsrednu nac I“
.tnaruatser eht ta thgin lufrednow a em dehsiw neht ,evaw dlim a saw
.noisivelet eht ot kcab gnikool
.gniraew detah I seohs evisnepxe esoht edisni hcterts ot
.eciov ym gniraeh nopu pu til elims siH
krad emaceb ti ecno stnemunom detanimulli fo ytsejam eht ot dnilb saw ydobon ,gnivird ro gniklaW
.reppus dah ew sa noos sa ti tuoba yenraB llet ot
,oga skeew elpuoc a em gnitrotxe deirt eH“
”?nekcihc tsewhtuos ro s’raseaC a tnaw uoy oD“
,toiR llawenotS eht rof dias eb osla thgim hcihW
.rorrim weivraer eht hguorht em ta dekool eh sa detnemmoc leehw eht dniheb rodarbaL ehT ”!taeb
.esuohnwot eht ta kcab
.niaga seye ym dellor I sa gnikrims ,dias yenraB
”.mmH“ .derekcins eH
.etammoor ysion a ro ,ot drawrof kool ot noitalosi evah t’ndid I ,ylikcuL
.tsehc mraw sih ot esolc em llup mih gnileef
.ereht devil nooccar redlo eht saw derettam taht lla
,deprihc regit eht
.gninworf mih ees t’ndid I
”.emit txen gninraw a uoy pils ot tegrof t’now I
,ti etirwer ot em detnaw eh ,nehT
.uoy morf sgniht gnipeek fo derit dna ,sessob
.rennid rof etal m’I
,redluohs sih no daeh ym detser dna sih htiw sregnif ym deniwtne I	         .tnemilpmoc taerg a deredisnoc eh gnihtemoS
”?nos ,rennid ot tuo og ot ydaer uoy era ,woN“ ”.haey ,haeY“
.regnol hcum saw ti ekil tlef dah ti tub
,nooccar redlo eht ot detaeper I sa nirg a otni rehtegot desrup spil ym
naillevaihcaM thgirnwod ro ,lacitircopyh ,dwerhs woh rettam oN
.sgnul ym depacse hgis yvaeh A
sa noisivelet eht no denrut dna teknalb eht ni flesym depparw d’I
dekil sa llew sa renid eht denwo ohw
.sih htiw sregnif ym depsalc neht ,demaeb eH
.noitseuq gib eht
nehW	         ”.snaicitilop mehT“
.sesulp-B otni s’F dna s’D sih nrut
ym dna em taht enola tel ,’dad‘
?neht ecnis thgiew tsol I daH .snirg gnihctam
.noitasrevnoc lausac
”,krowrepap fo bmob raelcun a dereffus eciffo s’reyolpme yM“
.sreksihw ruo otni tfaw sllems tnasaelp eht gnittel elihw mih deknaht yltnelis ew dna ,su fo tnorf ni setalp evitcepser ruo tes xof gnuoy ehT .seye ruo fo renroc eht fo tuo doof ruo gnirb yrreG was ew sa taes sih otni delttes neht ,dekramer eh ”,irB
,sthgilpots ta daer ot slammam gnivird rof sngis deirrac llits stsivitca detacided wef a
yllaicepsE“	            .slisnetu nwo ym dehctans I sa seye ym gnillor ,deilper I ”,rosseforP ,seY“
.yad suoutlumut eht morf
.spil desrup ym no tuo deid
.laicremmoc noitceleer wen a ni rats ot em ksa ylbaborp dluow flow dlo eht ,lleH .liab
edis eht no dalas sih gnivael elihw slesrom rellams otni kaets yciuj eht decils yletaciled yenraB
.nooccar redlo eht ta pu ylifoog
aciremA dna ,ht11 rebmetpeS no yad lufetaf taht ecnis sraey owt neve toN
ydobyreve ot dnim tsenoh rieht gnikaeps yb efil elbatrofmoc a devil reve
taht kniht uoy gnikam peek boj ruoy tel t’ndluohs uoy tuB“
,eninac redlo eht ot deddon yllufecrof I ”.thgiR“
,tuo desserts os demees uoY“
”?emit siht mih rof etirw ot uoy deggeb nosnhoJ deT .rM tahw em gnillet dnim ,oS“
erew stnerap sih ,elihwnaeM
,yrgnuh naht erom
.esaerg fo naelc sregnif ym depiw neht
”.rehtaf ym er’uoy enoyreve llet ot evah I hguone dab s’ti dna
sa lliw sih otni em gniyfidilos rehtruf
regit suomynope ehT
.huH“	         ”.eromyna sessalc ym dnetta t’ndluoc eh yhw gninialpxe rettel ygolopa na em gnivig saw eh ,dik eht was I emit tsal ehT .eromyna serutcel ym ni democlew t’nsaw eh naeD eht demrofni neht
.C.D fo mrots citoahc eht ni kcor ym ot nwod delims I
kool erus uoy
,ecap fo segnahc yppah erom ynam dnA“
,tuo ekops I ,em dniheb rood eht gnisolC
em evag nosnhoJ evitatneserpeR sknaht ylno ehT
.sgnillewd ytpme ot denruter em ekil sreffats detaicerpparednu dna
,oS“	         ”.yhtlaeh noloc
.level emos no ycerces
ni demrofsnart dah
.lausu eht rof tnew I
.tsaot a edam ew sa oot did eh
.sessenisub lacol ni sresiardnuf dekab-flah erew yeht ,netfo tsoM
?tey stnemugra SUTOCS eht nees uoy evaH
nehw syad dlo eht ssim em edam tI
,delttes sevlesruoy teg tsuj owt uoY
,hctorc sih ta elims ylekil d’I woh pu sgnirb
”.ton ro llew seod nosnhoJ fi ees ew retfa
.yaw yna ni reeuq eb ot emirc a ti edam hcihw swal dah
,uoy evol I .si ti revetahw
t’nseod ytisrevinu eht ,uoy gnillet peek I“
,txen eht deludehcser
,desucofnu ,detsuahxe saw I
esuohnwot citsur a saw ’rehtaf‘
snoisiced laiciduj etamitlu
,sicoV sumoD yb
”?gnihtemos ro rennid yrasrevinna na rof etal er’uoy ti ekat I“
gniyap rehtob ot tnaw t’ndid ylekil tub ,derac eh ekil dednuos nosnhoJ .peR esuaceb dna
.sixat ekat ot em detnaw yeht
.pets mottob s’riats eht ta roolf doowdrah eht dehcuot teef erab ym sa deredduhs I
,sthgil eht ffo nrut
sI“	         ”?su tuoba ssalc ruoy htiw nepo eb ot deen uoy did tub“ ,deggurhs I
,yltcaxe ,sraey net si ti ,tsacdaorb tsrif s’yrots siht fo emit tA  .”letoH kcirevaM“
t’ndiD“	         ”.yrrow ot uoy tnaw t’ndid
,rehtegot derewohs ew ,sdrawretfA .neht ecnis
gnilimS	         ”.eiteews ,uoy fo gnizama eb dluow taht kniht
detaler yllaciteneg eb reve dluoc yenraB dna em taht tsesolc eht ,gnihtyna fI
,wolg egnaro-ylprup a ni tnemunoM notgnihsaW eht tsac
,dekael eb dluoc desiver d’I tahw fo egdelwonk fi dna yenraB gnillet
,selttob ruo rof gnihcaeR
od ot detnaw I tahw redisnoc ot em desuac ti
”nwonK reveN tuB ,neeS syawlA“ saw sihT
?ecap fo egnahc a
?stnemugra laro ehT
fI“	         ”?taes lausu eht tnaw uoY
,naol rac eht
.stneve tnatropmi rof ytic eht ssorca namssergnoc eht wollof ot em ksa ro
,noitcif yrruf gnidaer/gnitirw elihw cisum evawropav ot gninetsil emit eerf sih sdneps ohw
etalfed dnim deugitaf ym tel I ,eraf eht gniyap dna bacixat a gniliah retfA	         .tem yeht
,haeY“	         .derepsihw I
.ruoh artxe na dniheb yats I detsisni thgirtuo nosnhoJ .peR ,revewoH
,egagtrom eht ffo gniyap llits er’ew ecnis
.ytilarom dnuora evlover t’ndid ti
,thgirla…“
,yadot oga sraey net
.ssenisub edis a sa gniretac
.rennid rof erehwemos yenraB teem ot dennalp I fi ro lufituaeb saw rehtaew eht fi yllaicepse ,emoh ecnatsid cinecs eht llorts ot dekil netfo I ,skcatta repins .C.D eht dna 11/9 fo stneve eht erofeB .erotskoob etirovaf ruo ,gnisiR adbmaL morf raf oot ton
.etirwer eht fo etirwer eht etirwer neht
,erofereht dednimer eb su teL
tey roines ym sraey neetruof ylno eb ot deneppah
uoy taht semitemos deirrow tsuj m’I“
.secnatsmucric eht etipsed ,krims a ni elzzum sih sekahs eH ”!seod yllatot ti
.taes eht tsniaga delrucnu dna delruc liat yM ”.huH“
.noitcaer ym ta delkcac yenraB sa smlap ym otni seye ym deirub I ,sih morf yawa wap ym gnilluP ”!doG ,hO“ ”.rennid
detrats snaicitilop emos
.moordeb derahs ruo etisoppo gnittis moorhtab eht otni flesti dediug ydob eros yM
deirT“	         ”?uoy deliamkcalb eH“
.deb tfos ruo ni dexaler ew sa no gnihton gniraew
elihw dehgual eh ”,ma I tahT“
dna nwod koob eht ecalp mih draeh neht
.rehtaf dega-elddim a fo trap eht dekool
em neewteb decnalg nooccar redle ehT	         ”?tsivitca
,haN“	         .nooccar redle eht ta deppiuq I
emas eht fo stluda neewteb xes lausnesnoc waltuo ton dluoc setats taht delur truoC emerpuS SU eht ecniS
ym morf sterces gnipeek fo derit ,yekcal a gnieb fo derit
er’uoY“ .em ta kcab gnikrims ,deffocs nooccar redlo
I“	         .eno emaceb gnihtaerb dna staebtraeh ruO
.dnopser t’ndid I hcihw ot ,deireuq eH
.eciohc ym edam I
,snoitalutargnoC .doof ruoy uoy gnirb
,reerac ym fo derit m’I
.senal eht otni bacixat eht dediug eh sa deprihc rodarbaL eht ”,neht yako ,hA“
,dneirfyob ym ta kcab demaeb I sa pal ym no yleerf dehsiws liat yM .deraeppasid
pu denael I ,niaga
.nosnhoJ .peR tuoba
.thgin taht retal nam lufrednow eht ot
I	         .tuhs desolc srood eht ro ffo denrut saremac eht nehw
.dapeton ynit sih no nwod delbbircs ymmoT
,dneirflrig nwo reh sah yroeht tra ni yenavluD .srM ,lleH .spu-
,etam ym ,rentrap ym
ecnedifnoc htiw yas dluoc I ,retal sraeY
.rennid yrotarbelec a gnivah erew ’rehtaf‘
revetahw ,degnahc revetahw
.sgnilbis dna rehtom ym htiw adirolF nrehtron ni devil ronod mreps lacigoloib ym woh
depleh ruf kcalb-dna-yarg ym fo gnihsurb cituepareht dna rewohs toh a ,llarevO
emohnwot eht ot kcab klaw regnol on I detsisni yletarapes yeht ,reyolpme tnerruc ym dna yenraB morf aionarap gniregnil ot eud ,yletanutrofnU
.eraf eht diap d’I retfa em dlot revird ixat rodarbaL eht
yllaicepse ,scitilop naciremA fo edaçaf eht dniheb was I
tuoba klat stidnup owt gnissentiw dna
,reyolpme nwo ym ekil hcuM
taes teliot desolc eht no dedlof yltaen sehtolc naelc fo riap a gnieeS
.revo detabed gnieb
.enil ’ssob eht gnisu tuohtiw uoy llac t’ndluoc dna krow ta pu thguac tog I .yenoh ,yrros m’I“
na ro ,tfihs driht fo gninnigeb eht gnidaerd
”.irB ,oot uoy evol I“
,traeh yb noitanitsed eht deticer I ”?ot erehW“
.elbat a ta elpuoc redlo eht ot gniklat fo elddim eht ni ydaerla ,revres rehto eht ta decnalg eH
.ecalpkrow ym fo sliated eht noitnem t’ndluoc I dna
,reffats lanoissergnoc a sa gnikrow nehW
si yrots s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.em ta kool ot elzzum sih denarc revird ehT ”.raeh ot taerG“
,deb ni em ot esolc mih gnigguH
llits esac SUTOCS eht denoitnem enildaeh swen eht erehw
”?yako ,rennid rof od ot tahw tuo erugif ll’ew dna
,meht rof etov ot stneutitsnoc rieht ecnivnoc ro eil rehtie nemssergnoc gnipleh
krow pu gnirb I emityna gninworf pots t’dluoc uoy
,emoselohw eht fo eno ekil gnileef saw I
.swen gnineve eht gnihctaw
a ekil gnileef em tfel tI
.spets elbram enitsirp eht pu deztlaw I emit hcae
rehtaR	         ”!draeh reve d’I tsrow eht erew stnemugra s’.G.A taht
.ytrebiL ydaL ekil denethgirb nirg siH ”?ton yhW .erus
”.taht em llac t’nod esaelp
eruS“	         ”?snotuorc artxe emos teg I nac dnA“
.noisiced ym tuoba mih dlot I
lrucnu liat nooccar ym tel I
saw nam dnahthgir sih wenk eh ylno fI“
.swen gnineve eht dna ylimaf dednetxe rieht gnissucsid elpuoc dlo
.raey txen litnu tiaw ot tnaw tsael ta uoy
tnemtnioppasid ehT
.ciffart dekcolb keew roirp eht morf stsetorp raw-itna retfa yllaicepsE
’.toidi na m’I kniht yeht ro ,tsissicran a er’yeht sselnu
tahW“	         ”—tub ,gnihtyna ro egnahc fo naf gib a ton er’uoy wonk I dna
”,moT ,thginot sraey
I“	         ”?em llet uoy t’ndid yhW“
,elucidir rieht ot desopxe sselnu nwonk reven tub
rof tuo yddad sih
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ecnatirehni fo yaw eht ni gnitteg morf sredistuo elbarelotni yna
,nees sgniht suoirav eht tuoba no dna no og dluoc
,dedda neht ,derettum yenraB ”,tsewhtuoS“
.emitnwod rieht ni did snaciremA gnihtyreve dna gnihtyna tsomla ni depees scitilop dna
eht dootsrednu I ,gnihtyna fI
”.yaw eht yb ,uoy evol I“
emoh nruter ot em rof emit saw ti decnuonna I nehw
.rood moorhtab eht fo llaw tfel eht no emarf a ni gnuh hcihw morf tnemom a
”!sruoy fo etad yrasrevinna siht no nuf evaH“
.erutpac s’niessuH maddaS fo tneve eht ni hguone doog eb dluow mih rof etirw depleh
.swap ruo ekahs ot drawrof gnippets ylippah elihw derrup eH
.noitaromemmoc a si flesti edirP hcihw fo
.llafthgin yb dekool .C.D ,notgnihsaW lufituaeb woh revo teg t’ndluoc llits I ,emas eht deyats ro degnahc sgniht hcum woh rettam oN
,desoporp neht ,delims eH
kcab tup eb ot dedeen ew ,esiwrehtO
.staes ruo otni dexaler neht ,niaga regit eht deknaht eW	         ”!niaga
yats ot mih detnaw ylimaf dednetxe sih dna ,daed gnol
,taht em sllac nosnhoJ“
.thgiR“	         ”?yako ,neht emit doog a evah dad ruoy dna uoY“
dennalp I dna ,edam neeb dah
,noisiced lanif ym detnemec tI
”,yppah uoy sekam ti fi
moordeb ruo ni evol wols gnikam I dna yenraB htiw dedne thgin lufrednow ehT	         *** ”.evol ym
tnediserP a ekil leef ot desu I
”,nuf attol elohw a ekil sdnuos taht ,em uoy eveileb ,hO“
eniN	         .efil etavirp a ot thgir eht dah yenraB dna em ekil ydobemos rehtehw ediced dluow slaudividni eniN
.C.D evivrus ot gnilggurts
.etalp sih no kaets gnikool-suoiciled )yldettimda( eht fo ecils egral a gniwollaws retfa elims gnirussaer a em gnivig ,dedda eh
reyolpme ym teY .tey ytriht
,ruf ym nwod dehsaw yad gnol eht fo sesserts eht llA
,hseehS“	         .revird eht ot neht
sih nevig ,enod naht dias reisae saw ti tub ,krow tuoba gniklat diova ot tseb ruo deirt eW
”,yenraB ,yrgna eb d’uoy kniht t’ndid
sserttam letoh a ekil tlef taeskcab eht ni gnittiS
osla ohw ,tesolc eht ni dneirf wollef a yb nekat neeb d’tI .hpargotohp eht ta tnemom a rof deregnil I
I“	         .gnorw yteixna ym devorp yltalf mih htiw evol ni gnieb fo sraey neves nehw
.gniralb ylneddus enohp enildnal
hcum woh dna ,serutcel s’yenraB otni deyalp ti hcum woh ,qarI fo noisavni eht no snoinipo )wol(
stnih ynam oot ffo evig thgim
.dekool adnutor eht lufituaeb woh yb dezama eb ot desu I ,emit a nopu
;esrow ro ,tnedicca yb detserra eb ot em detnaw rehtieN
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
,spil ym ot esolc denael eH ”.heH“
seirrow ym ,niaga ecnO	         ”.irB
.niaga deilper I ”,yas t’naC“
”,traehteews ,gniht
”,ydaerla nekat ton s’ti
,drawni tekcaj ym gnicalp retfa taes denoihsuc eht otni dils I	         .thgin
,saxeT gnidulcni ,setats 41  .redneg
,naecO citnaltA eht decaf eW
.oot gnilkcuhc pu dedne I .gnihgual god eht ot del hcihw ,denaorg I
oot klat t’nac I wonk uoY“
,tsihcosam citirhtra na ekil elkcarc t’ndid sbmil ym
,noitcele laitnediserp txen eht retfa ,tsael tA“
.hgU“ .noitcerid sih ni sdrow lufroloc wef a dias ev’dluow I ,cilbup ni tuo t’nerew ew fI
.em ot denrut neht
kniht neve t’ndid I dna
.tnemesuma sih ot hcum ,niaga deredduhs liat yM
sa steknalb eht rednu rehtegot deltsur sliat nooccar ruo
”.eiteews ,melborp oN“	         .delbmum I
.yteicos fo trap gnieb
,swap htob htiw nwod parw nekcihc toh gnimaets ym tes ylluferac I
hcihw ,ylippah dekramer eh
ycavirp ruo deulav ew ecniS
oT“	         ”?sraey neves rehtona oT“
.enim htiw elttob sih fo ssalg eht deknilc eh
,daeherof ym ssik mih tlef I	         ”.uoy evol
,tsrow eht demussa I ,niaga ecnO
,ffulb sih dellac I ,lleW
.eciffo eht fo tuo
,esruoc fO“	         .detseggus I
.dnalyraM fo redrob eht raen erehwemos renid cissalc a
detneverp em tpoda yenraB gnivaH
fo secneuqesnoc eht revo gnilluM
.srae gninetsil morf raf ,renid eht fo renroc raf eht ni eb ot deneppah noitseuq ni htoob
.rethgiarts gnittis ,feilebsid ni depsag I
”,thgin doog a evaH“
,ssergnoC rof reffats level-yrtne na sa ffo gnitratS
,yad hcae yratilim ruo yb edam sedirts eht retto na htiw gnissucsid elihw delims flow-ehs A
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.koob sih gnidaer deunitnoc eh sa seye ym gnisolc
emitrevo od ot deksa eb ot hguone gnol tiaw naht
.gnineve ym niur ot ytinutroppo rehtona mih evig t’ndid I ,oS .edistuo gnitiaw sbacixat fo hsur eht ssim ot em rof hguone gnol egatsoh em tpek ydaerla dah nosnhoJ
ruo tuoba klat did eW
”.esuoh eht ot kcab emac uoy ecnis ecaf ruoy no kool siht dah ev’uoY
owt ehT .emoh eurt ym ot edisni gnippils
selims dna hctorc nwo rieht ta nwod skool ydoboN‘ ,mih llet I dna“
a otni kcab deppils I dna yenraB ,evirra ot doof ruo rof detiaw ew sA
moorhtab dellif-maets eht detixe neht
yrotsih ni lauxesomoh ro
”!sdneirf ym ,nairB
,sraey evif rof detner neeb ylno dah yrautcnas ruo dellac ew esuohnwot yrots-
,rentrap ym ot ylesolc deltsen I
,gnol a retfa detrap spil ruO
,niaga ti etirwer
.swoble ym desserac
,gnirewsna nehw tnecca nisnocsiW kciht sih nwod denot neht
I“	         ”.detceleer tog nagaeR ecnis gnihcaet neeb s’ehs dna
.eb ot dedeen ti naht redriew noitautis eht ekam ot syaw gnidnif ni elbarolped
.derit…tsuj m’I“ .dedda I
.kaets eht no detnemmoc eh sa parw
”.eivom dlo na hctaw ot gniog er’ew dna sregrub naem emos gnikooc s’eH“ ,dias I sa hteet ym hguorht gniyl ,ylsuovren deggurhs I ”.erehwoN“
etah I kniht uoy sekam tahw dnA“
.ti erongi t’ndid flah tnavresbo-reve yM .ot deddon I
”.lla dna yrasrevinna ruo s’ti ecniS
”?yllaeR“	         .deksa eH ”?taht deirt
”,stnioppasid reven ymmoT“
”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“ ,levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
,hE“ .kooc ot deen t’ndid ew doof gnitae fo thguoht eht ta deyaws liat yM
,oS“ .ybab dezitpab
,oS“	         .ylsuoires sa stneve tnerruc gnikat ton stneduts emos fo devorppasid eh
.nwod dewols eciov ym ni noitarepsaxe ehT ”.wonk I ,wonk
?dnim ruoy no gnihtemos sI“
,sriats eht fo mottob eht ta desum eh
.em no llef seye ynagoham gniraedne sih nehw
neveS“	         ”.yrasrevinna ruo s’tI“
!semit lla fo thginot dna
:eb ot ,ecno ,saw ti tahw fo dna ,deveihca yrasrevinna siht tahw fo
ruo ekil ,stnemom reippah ot derapmoc
gniyojne tbuod oN
”?yenraB ,samajap fo daetsni sehtolc yad yhw
tub etalp eht otno efink dna krof sih deppord nooccar redle ehT ”.gnittiuq
.dedlof yltrap srae yM
,llew…tuo dnif yeht nehw uoy liamkcalb ot yrt ll’yeht dna
”nwonK reveN tuB ,neeS syawlA“
saw yenraB ,mih devol I sa hcum sA
pu ti ekam ot flesym dnimer yltnelis dna
.redderhs eht otni srepap pu delpmurc ro dessot eht lla pu gninaelc setunim ytriht rehtona dneps ,sulP
.yal sfeileb ym erehw htiw emaceb sgniht reraelc eht ,revewoh ,detsal
yrreG ro flesym rehtie evah ll’I dna
,eit krow ym denetsafnu ,noitisop dexaler a otni
.niard eht otni deitpme neht
.niaga nemssergnoc rehto htiw gnikrow reve morf em tsilkcalb neht dna em erif ylpmis d’eh ,tseb tA .kcatta traeh a reffus ylbaborp dluow flow rebmit dlo eht teb I
.rettam t’ndid ti tub
.etalp ysaerg eht no laem denodnaba ym ta nwod gnirats detrats I sa tuo detniop I ”,namssergnoc egnahc I revenehw naf a ton er’uoY“ ”.egnahc laudarg
,yad ro thgiN .nwo ym no
.skcab ruo no sehtolc eht dah ylerab ew ,rehtegot ni devom tsrif ew nehW
,hgis deyonna na tuo tel flow rebmit thgiewrevo ehT
sa su redisnoc t’ndid elpoep thgiarts
stsirw dna selkna ym ni niap tnioj ylrae fo stceffe eht gnileef
I“	         .egap rehtona gninrut nopu derumrum eH ”?irB
?nairB ,ssalc ni yadot denrael ew evah tahw ,woN“
.sevil yliad rieht ni erew ew detargetni woh tuoba gnikniht neve tuohtiw ecnetsixe ruo ta gniffocs dekil yeht
.ssenidrat ym tuoba ssorc oot eb t’ndluow yenraB ,yllufepoH
ew t’nod yhw ,oS .emoh gnimoc erofeb dedeen ew ffuts eht teg ot oot ytisrevinu eht ta yadot ysub oot neeb ev’I dna
nehctik eht morf tnemevoM
.em detcerroc yenraB ”.ot
yenraB htiw pihsnoitaler ym regnol ehT
tuoba gnikniht…m’I“
gnignirb s’eh dna ,omoh a
troter A  .pu thguorb eh
,em ta deworran seye ediw siH
ym htiw devil I taht gninoitnem terger em edam tsomla ti yas yltneconni mih gniraeH
”?uoy t’ndid ,yadot oga sraey neves yltcaxe srepap noitpoda eht ngis ot em deggeb uoy ,won ,woN“
,nees syawla erew eW
.era somoh eht lla erehw tuo erugif ot tuo s’enoyreve
”.nairB ,yrasrevinna yppaH .oot uoy evol
,meht tcapmi t’ndid ylekil taht
”?irB ,niaga ni gnikcik aionarap ruoy siht
,dlot eb hturT	         .elpoep
,siht gniod peek t’nac tsuj I-I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.detcepxe d’I ekil em ta eralg t’ndid
.emit eht ta esnes lacigol tsom eht edam ti
,scitilop senecs-eht-dniheb otni enog reve d’I nosaer tseggib eht
.repapswen sih fo egap a gninrut elihw dehgual eh
”.enif eb ot gniog si hcihw fo llA“	         ”—sllib ruo
”,esnes a ni ,yddad ruoy ma I tuB“
,dnim ym fo kcab eht ot esle gnihtyreve
.spets ym dewols I
,evil ot dah ew yaw eht taht oga hguone gnol htob si hcihw
tnorf ni desop ew sa rehto hcae dnuora depparw smra
,ffo ti nrut ot etomer eht rof gnihcaeR
,hguoht yrots dnoces eht fo sllaw eht denil taht sgniward dna sotohp eht ta gnikooL
tsoM	         .noitcele 4002 eht retfa
.eson sih no decnalab selcatceps gnidaer
.sdrawpu ylwols klaw em gnihctaw
delims I dna ,ssik lausnes
.sekoj worb-wol htiw serutcel ym tpurretni nac yeht kniht ohw stneduts yttarb rof hguoht moor evah t’nod I“
,seot ym ta loop a otni delkcirt
.em dniheb taes eht tsniaga deggaw liat yM ”?emos evah llits
.sevil rieht ni devlovninu
”.ti tog ,dalas tihsllub a
.stsiybbol dna snaicitilop rof dekrow I rehtruf eht dedecer yllaudarg em ni etevian ehT
.spets tnorf s’esuohnwot eht gniees ta delims neht
ym htiw derahs I tnemtrapa ehT
.niaga slisnetu sih gnibbarg
.raen ylgnikcohs eb ot hguone tnecer llits dna
sraey suorutnevda s’yenraB morf dneirf raed a saw
uoy fi ,reeb renemhöB fo selttob owt dnA“
”,erutcel ym gnirud enohp pilf sih ta nwod gnikool s’eh wonk I woh sksa sbocaJ
.tesolc eht ni peed gniniamer saw tuoba yrrow ot dedeen I dna yenraB taht lla
tneduts remrof a dias I fi em eveileb uoy
.slaicremmoc noitceleer sih ni edulcni ot dekil netfo eh sklof ylredle naciremA-llA
.eciffo eht ta tnaligivrepyh eb syawla ot dedeen eno
deksa tsrif I ecnis yb tnew emit hcum woh etaicerppa em edam ti
ssik etanoissap a otni em gnidiug nooccar redlo eht ,tcaf nI
,snoitalutargnoC“	         .nirg thgirb a htiw ni demihc yenraB
.moor gnivil eht otni sriatsnwod ti edam d’I ecno nooccar eht deksa I
elucsinim tlef yeht tub ,suoutlumut neeb dah semit ,yad tneserp eht ot sey dias eh nehw emit eht morF
”.nairB ,ot evah t’nod eW“
”.parw hcnar nocab a evah
,tpoda ot dah ew seigetarts eht
eht rof esac eht t’nsaw ti ,yletanutroF .yaw rehtie su fo daeha ti nekat dah esle ydobemos fi rehtona no delttes evah d’ew ,llitS .tops eht derreferp ew
,rehtaf evitpoda ym dna em tuoba hturt eht wenk reve nosnhoJ deT evitatneserpeR fI .egduj a ot gniog tuohtiw egairram a fo stifeneb eht lla evag srepap ehT
.oot liat nooccar regnuoy ym fo thgis eht
,sicoV sumoD yb
”?thgir ,noisavni qarI eht ro esac wal ymodos eht tuoba rehtie s’ti teb I“
”?eiteews ,uoy ta dam eb ll’I kniht uoy sekam
.esle gnihtyreve tegrof yltnatsni em edam niaga seye ynagoham emosdnah sih otni gniratS
dlo siht peek annaw I fi doof deirf diova ot deen I syas rotcoD ?hguoht
feiler dna nrecnoc otni detlem
seot ym dewolla neht
,redluohs sih no niaga daeh ym detser neht
dehsup I ,flesym ot gnihgiS
sih yb detpurretni eb ot ylno ,ksed sih ta srepap dna srettel gnidaer deunitnoc nosnhoJ .peR
”.nairB ,thgin dooG .oddik ,ahcteb uoY“	         ”.ris ,uoy knahT“
.deilper ylderit I ”,yas t’naC“
.nikpan dedlof a no meht tes yltaen neht ,slisnetu sih pu dekcip eh ,daetsnI
”.deirrow em dah uoy ,segassem txet on ,sllac enohp oN“ .tekcaj ym ekat ot drawrof gnippets elihw denaorg eh ”,nairB ,droL dooG“