rof tnaem saw ytrap eht yug eht yhw
.deid ehs retfa stbed gnilbmag sih ffo yap ot ti dlos rehtorb ruoy tub
.deretne eh sa mih dnuora llef snoollab lufroloc ,tsriF
,sriats eht pu deirruh luaP sa dedda eH
,ecarbme eht gnikaerB
”?thgir lla uoy erA ?deneppah tahW“
gnirehtag egral a rof timrep a teg ot hguorht og ot dah I tihs ehT
?yllaeR“   ”.tsol tog I…I“
”.gnirebmemer rof uoy knaht …dnA“
.ti s’taht dna sgnidliub owt dnif ot erehw wonk ylno I
”?gnidliub gninrub a morf snahpro fo hcnub a evas ot dah uoY
gnidulcni seirots ysatnaf setirw ohw
.pu wohs ,boj eno dah eH .boj enO“
!melborp nmad ruoy s’taht ,luaP ,’ot naem‘ reven uoY“   ”—ot
wefruc retfa tuo saw eH
!ti tog I ,oN ?5
yb emoh eb ot uoy deksa I taht togrof uoY .tiaw on ,oN
.rehto hcae dessim tsuj yeht gnitacidni
;retsac cigam a gnieb tuoba detah eh gniht eno eht saw tI
?cigam dezirohtuanu rof gninrom eht ni mrof nmad a tuo llif ot evah dnA“   .deksa luaP
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.gnihtyna yas neve dluoc luaP erofeb esor selkcah siH
,ekarD navE yb ”ssendniK fo tcA nA“
.ecaf sih gnihcuot morf mih peek ot
.won ti gnidiova on saw erehT
.tuo kcab yaw eht no togrof tub
.knas traeh sih
dehgis dnuoh dlo ehT
!taht eganam neve t’ndluoc eh dnA
”?uoy did ,evil uoy erehw derebmemer yllaniF“   .esle erehwyna
.edisni dekcut xob yrlewej eht gnibbarg ,tekcop sih rof dehcaer ylevitcnitsni luaP   .deksa salciN
,ytic eht ssorca raelc saw erots eht dnA“
.kcen s’luaP dnuora smra sih werht eh nehw raelc emaceb rewsna eht tub ,llet ot elbissopmi saw
”.esle erehwyna og su tel t’nod yehT
dluoc eh tseb sa ruf dna sehtolc sih denethgiarts eH
”.sees dna ni semoc enoemos erofeb pu yrruh woN
hU“   ”.pots yellort eht morf skcolb evif eht
,deilper eh ,nirg hsipeehs a gnireffO
?gnippirt yb flesruoy ot egamad hcum siht did uoY .yrros m’I“
noitasrevnoc drawkwa na gnidiovA
suoethgir os era sdratsab esoht skniht enoyreve raews I“
”?pu wohs ot derehtob leef t’ndid
.retnuoc eht no denael dna detrons nagroM   ”--I…lleW“
.nehctik eht dna moor gnivil eht neewteb
teef sih ta derats luaP
hserf saw ,draugthgin eht ,salciN fo llems ehT
.kcap eci na dna tik dia-tsrif a htiw mih denioj nagroM
”.ot og ot ’dewolla‘ er’uoy seno ot yaw eht wonk uoy ecniS
.mih htiw tespu oot
,gnignits eht morf tub
.tekcaj sih ffo deppils eh sa htaerb sih rednu erows luaP .mih dedlocs
?taht ekil gnihtemos rof
tnar yrgna eht gniraeh nopu detatiseh eh tuB
.nwod gniwols fo noitnetni on dah eh tub
?sruoh evif tsal eht rof yrrow em gnikam roF
.kcap eci eht htiw ecaf eht ni mih deppals yllacitcarp eH
seno ecin eht fo eno saw salciN
gnieb rof nwonk saw salciN .reganeet a ekil
”.xis erew uoy ecnis lenneK ni devil ev’uoY
.gnihtyna ro dekcatta t’nsaw I
”.emit ni kcab ti ekam dluoc I thguoht tsuj I .t’ndid I ,I“
”.gnihton s’tI .enif m’I ,oN“
,nohtaram kcolb-evif eht retfa tsrub ot ydaer tlef sgnul siH
thginot ni yaw eht no neve dna
:eluR snogarD erehW
.nehctik eht ssorca deirruh eh dna ecaf sih morf deniard regna eht llA
.tsrub hcamots sih litnu retaw knird ot naht erom gnihton detnaw eh dna yrd htuom sih tfel dah gninnur taht llA
,ti ekil tsuj hcaorb a dah rehtomdnarg ruoy dias uoY“
.yrrufoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,tnessiD
saw yad ym erus ekam ot
.gniggurhs ,deilper luaP
,eno emas tcaxe eht si siht fi wonk t’nod I
.yawyna ti gnitacsifnoc morf sdraug emos pots t’ndluow taht tub
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mih denimaxe eh sa dnuora ecaf sih denrut dna
.lla retfa ytrap esirprus a mih nworht dah nagroM
,retteb yna leef uoy sekam ti fI“
,deraelc noisiv sih ecnO
,mih hctac dluoc lortap gnissap yna erehw edistuo dnats ot suoregnad saw tI
.noitanitsed sih morf gnimoc
”?tahw tsuJ“   ”—tsuj s’ti ,yrros m’I dna ,taht wonk I“
dna erots eht ot yawflah tsuj ,haN“
”?yadot taht od ot evah yllaer uoy did tuB“
.tnil fo llab gniklaw a elbmeser mih gnikam
”?klawedis eht yb depmuj tog uoy gninnur siht lla neewteb erehwemos gnisseug m’I oS .huh-
.gnidliub eht ot noitnetta sih denrut eh
”?niaga emoh dna erots eht ot yaw eht fo tser eht nar uoy oS“
”?ksa em ekam ot gniog yllaer uoy era ro ,wefruc retfa tuo er’uoy yhw nialpxe ot gniog uoy era oS“
,ruf nat sih dekcehc-elbuod eh
.eye neerg a elbmeser ti gnikam
.yawa dekcab dna deneffits luaP   ”—os s’eH
.emoc ot saw tahw gniwonk dehgis eh ”…I…I
.noisserpxe napdaed a htiw mih ta derats nagroM   ”.deppirt I“
,52 ta neve
.ti teg ot dah I ,ti was I nehw tub ,’locotorp‘
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.elbat eht ta tas eh sa
.tekcop sih fo tuo xob yrlewej llams eht dellup dna flesmih desopmoc ylkciuq luaP
?uoy ot deneppah tahw tuB
”ssendniK fo tcA nA“   yojne esaelP
.gninrom litnu tiaw dluoc snoitasrevnoc drawkwa yna dna
,kooL“ .sriats eht dednecsed dna
.nwod gnillews eht peek ot ereht no taht dloH“
.ecaf sih pu gnirevoc on saw ereht dna
”.ti ta kool a ekat ll’I dna nwod tiS“
,emit no erew uoy ,yadhtrib ym nO
”.’reggum a morf ydal dlo na devas I‘ sa gnirettalf sa yltcaxe ton s’tI
naem t’ndid I“
.dnatsrednu nac I tahT
,nekorb s’gnihtyna ekil kool t’nseod tI .uoy knaht oN
”.ssendnik ym rof dedrawer ylsuoreneg eb dluow I woh dna eb dluow uoy lufetarg woh tuoba gnikniht saw I
.yrlewej gnivah su tuoba leef yeht woh wonk uoY
.og ot erehwon dah eh taht tuo detniop
”—yaw eht no nwod ekorb yellort eht nehT
.reffo ot yrt annog er’uoy esucxe emal revetahw
elims ot ton gniyrt saw eh tnaem taht rehtehW
draobroolf esool eht tuoba togrof eh ,yletanutrofnU
,mih gnitruh diova ro
”.gniht eht yub ot timrep eht tog yllanif I tub ,ssa fo tol a ssik dna sgnirts emos llup ot daH“   ”.yrlewej
.ria fo splug egral nwod kcus dna llaw eht no nael ot tnemom a koot dna deppots eh
thginot gnitteg er’uoy ’drawer‘ ylno ehT“ ,dias dna mra eht ni mih dehcnup nagroM
revo uoy ot deneppah gnihtemos fi referp yllautca I emahs a s’ti wonk uoY“
.elbuort ni mih teg ot gniog ylno saw gniyL
.stnecs yna rof deffins eh ,efas eb ot tsuJ
tegrof t’ndid I ,oN“
,timmus thgilf-evif eht fo pot eht tA
emit emas eht ta deppots riap ehT
.ekatsim sih dezilaer eh sa denrub srae s’luaP fo sedisni ehT
”?cigam esu annog ton er’uoY“
,skcans rof nehctik eht otni gnikaens nehw ti dediova syawla eH
gniliec eht morf gnignah llits ”!yadhtriB yppaH“ gnidaer rennab eht
.kram fo dnik emos saw ereht
.hctaw sih ta nwod dekool eh
.tsehc ediw sih ssorca smra sih dedlof salciN sa ylsuovren dennirg luaP .derats dna
.yaw eht yb ,yadot rof ylno saw hcihw—
,dne no gnidnats ruf depirts kcalb dna yerG
,elddim eht ni tes enotsmeg eht htiw
.detcepxe naht retal saw ti tub wefruc dessim dah eh wenk eH
.htarw s’dneirfyob sih gnicaf erofeb pat eht morf gniknird dna
.elbuort esrow hcum ni eb dluow eh
rehto hcae gnilcric sdrib owt fo epahs eht ni dengised neeb dah tI
.deddon dna delims luaP
sdinac ddo-ytnewt eht ot nialpxe ot gnivah tuoba woh rO
”.tnemevap gnissik dnuora gninnur tsuj er’uoy dna uoy tuoba kcis deirrow saw I eveileb t’nac I
.rotaregirfer eht rof dedaeh dna pu tog eH
sremaerts lufroloc htiw demarf dna
.yllarutan laeh ot enif eb dluohs ti os
,llah eht nwod klaw eht fo tser eht roF
deneppah tahW ?ti si tahw oS
,hguoht ,emit txeN“   ”.emitynA“
llewriats eht fo esab eht ot ti edam tsuj eH
”?yadhtrib ruoy retfa litnu tiaw tsuj uoy nac
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?ti t’nsaw srehctaw nmad esoht saw tI
.edisni dedaeh neht
.eciton t’ndluow uoy gnipoh adnik saw I“
,tnirps lluf ta teerts eht nwod dehsur luaP    ekarD navE yb
.emit a ta owt sriats eht pu dednuob dna kcul sih desruc dna deknaht luaP
.ylper s'etoyoc eht saw elkcuhc rettib A
,noitazirohtua tuohtiw teerts eht no mih thguac yeht fi
.flesym tuoba gnikniht saw I“
.gninetsil t’nsaw enilef eht demussa eh
.sriats eht sdrawot tperc dna kcul sih deknaht luaP
nihc eht yb luaP depsarg eH
llef srae s’luaP
.ytpme yllufknaht saw ybbol ehT
.mih llik annog m’I esuaceb yako s’eh epoh I
.selit eht ssorca delffuhs eh hcihw
.skrow llits hctaw ym dna
.ereh dnuora era yeht tcirts woh wonk uoy ,no emoC“
,gnisuma ti dnif dluow luaP ,yllamroN
.enod saw yad eht litnu emit hcum toN
,hO !emoh gnimoc mih tuoba yrrow dna sehsid eseht fo lla gnihsaw thgin ym dneps ot evah I woN
.renroc eht dnuora emac salciN nehw
detaert gnieb llits saw eh
”.hguone esolc saw ti derugif I tub
”.rehto hcae egassem ot cigam esu ew nehw ti ekil t’nod yeht wonk uoY“
t’nsaw nagroM yllufepoH
ydaerla peelsa saw etoyoc eht ,ykcul saw eh fI
.uoy teg t’nod tsuj I ,wonk’Y“
?srehctaw eht fo eno yb pu dleh tog uoy oS“   ”.skrow
si yrots s’yadoT dna
?tisiv uoy did sgnidliub ’neddibrof‘ eseht fo hcihw dnA“
”?setunim evif rof flesruoy tuoba kniht ot
.sthgil eht no denrut dna dlohserht eht dessorc eh sa reitliug leef mih edam yletaidemmi tnemtrapa eht fo edisni ehT
?tae reven dluow uoy laem a revo evals em gnikam roF ?tahw rof yrroS“   ”—I .yrroS“
”!?hsinif em tel uoy lliW“
.erofeb sruoh nur eht ot erapmoc t’ndid niap eht ,sediseB
.thguoht eh ,erom tuo krow ot deen ylsuoires I
.ssensselkcer sih desruc dna ezorf eH
,wefruc tsap ydaerla saw tI
mih tuoba yrrow nagroM gnivaH
”,sessik ruoy referp I
”,esle enoemos ot ti lles ot gniog saw eh ,yadot mih diap I sselnu em dlot yug eht ,lleW“
.ylhsipeehs deilper luaP
.thgis ni saw gnidliub tnemtrapa eht ;esolc os saw
”?uoy htiw emas eht od em tel uoy t’nac yhW .tcefrep
.ecnaraelc noitatropelet em evig annog yeht erew yaw on dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.oN“   "—os tsuj er’yeht tub
moorhtab eht otni gnikaens deredisnoc eh tub ,elbissop t’nsaw thgin lla
.efil sih ni hcum os denrub reven dah shgiht dna tsehc sih tub
uoy llik ti dluoW“
”,norom gnikcuf uoY“
.od ot dah eh lla saw tahT
.gnicap deppots nagroM
.nirg eht deppord luaP
.ecaf sih fo edis tfel eht no borht llud eht morf mih detcartsid
.mih htiw secnahc sih ekat rehtar dluow luaP
.mih ecaf ot gninrut ,deksa nagroM
.trap tseisae eht saw emoh gnitteg ,yletanutrofnU
tsirw s’nagroM debbarg ylkciuq luaP
”?emit no emoh emoc ot derehtob eb t’ndluoc uoy taht
dna mp 51:11 daer ecaf stI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.esrow leef mih edam tsuj yrujni sih dniheb hturt eht gniwonk
devil eh hsiw mih edam ti won tub
.nehctik eht tuoba decap dna doots eH
”.elbaveil-gnikcuf-ebnU
.ksir eht htrow t’nsaw ti tub
”.uoy rof ecin gnihtemos od dluow I derugif I os ,eno detnaw syawla uoy dias uoY
noitanitsed lanif eht nehw toN
.liat sih dehtooms dna
.desuma ton saw etoyoc ehT
.seye sih ni gninetsilg eht edih t’ndid ti tub ,yawa denrut eH
”.tser s’thgin doog a dna laem toh a si
,ti ta kool a teg t’ndid eH
”.modeerf yna evah su tel reven selohssa esohT
?ytrap esirprus a uoy gninnalp saw ti drah woh wonk uoY
,ekarD navE yb ”ssendniK fo tcA nA“ saw sihT
,sehtolc ytrid sih tuo denethgiarts
,eno detnaw syawla eh denoitnem dah eh nehW
.ekorb hctaw ruoy :em llet t’noD“
”.yadhtrib yppah dnA“
.esor srae ’salciN
tsehc dna sgel sih ni ssenthgit eht ,gnihtyna fI
fo esuaceb ti ekat uoy tel t’ndluow yeht taht erew uoy tespu woh wonk I
.edisni hcaorb dlareme na gnilaever ,xob eht denepo eH
.nehctik eht drawot detrats eH
,gnidliub tnemtrapa eht dehcaer yllanif eh ecnO
;srevaew rehto eht htiw tneinel dna eltneg erom
.tsehc dna sgel sih ni niap eht gnirongi
.gnikaerb eciov sih ,dias nagroM
gnihtyreve did uoY
edis lanoitar erom eht tub
,lagelli gnihtyna niatnoc t’ndid tI
.tcere liat dna ediw seye derats nagroM
.enola uoy evael ll’I os ,yawyna uoy llik annog si nagroM
”?etal eb annog erew uoy pu sdaeh a em dnes dna yrt ot kniht t’ndid uoy dnA“
,rood eht tuo nur dna nrut ot demaercs luaP fo trap yrevE
.dehctiwt ecaf s’nagroM
.tneserp erew uoy
ecnaraelc teg neve uoy did woH“
,etats detaluger-imes a ot denruter dah gnihtaerb sih ecnO