,renwo ym fo erawa yrev saw I step tsom ekil ,seY
,egnahc sgniht erom eht mees dluow tI
.snoitasrevnoc ni gnigagne
.nwod kaerb ton did ehS
.htrow er’yeht lla rof kwauqs dna
.tnereffid yllatot si meht susrev su rof dekan ,esruoc fO
…enasni doog fo dnik a eb ot ti deredisnoc ylpmis eW
.em toohs ot gniog saw ehs diarfa saw yltsenoh I
…dnatsrednu fo dnik I dna
.enasni morf raf era ylurt ohw ytinamuh gnoma esoht era ereht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.emas eht yats ylpmis yeht erom eht
.pleh ton did sksaM
.ni yltnerruc ma I noitautis eht ot em del tahw si sihT
.erofeb namuh a htiw dekan neeb reven d'I   xoF yyxiV yb ”yhcranA“    :yojne esaelP
.gniht emas eht rof dehsiw gnivah ot dettimda ehS
.serutaerc yls dna ykcirt yrev era yehT
,tuo rehto hcae tlef ew syad wef a roF
,retirw thguat- fles a si ehS
.enohp llec reh yb derutpac saw uoy htiw derahs evah I egami ehT
rehtegot knurd teg
:notgnihsaW no hcram sgoD
etoyoc ruoy ,ozirraC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.sgniht fo yaw eht ni eciov llams yrev a ma I tub ,noitautis eht fo eganioc siht htiw eergasid thgim I
.dloheb ot thgis a ylurt si namuh dekan a taht yas llits lliw I
.pleh ton did stius mreG
.tnew ti yaw hcihw rettam on ,tnemom eht erutpac ot detnaw dna ,tcaer dluow I woh erus t’nsaw ehs ,tniop taht tA
ENO ON ,TAEPER I ,ENO ON
.nwo ym no rood eht kcolnu ot elba saw I
.truoc eht no etoyoc ruoy gnieb yad eno fo
.ralloc eulb yliramirp emoceb evah sdeerb xiM
.rehtie pleh ton did ytrap diaR a ta seilf ekil gnippord elpoeP
.emoceb evah ot mees yeht ytoons erom eht era yeht derberup erom eht dna
.enasni ytinamuh deredisnoc syawla evah slamina EW
.doog os erew yehT
gninrom gniwollof eht dna
,egac ym ni thgin taht peels ot tnew I
:gnignahc yldipar si
…on tub ,elggig a dda dna ereh taorht ym raelc dluohs I
ENOG YTINAMUH SAH
;detceffa si dlrow eritne ehT
.od llits dna …evol edam ew seY
.gnilbbin eot eht sunim fo tros tsuj ,taht yltcaxe llits si gnikam evol tsop ruo fo hcum dna
snoitpircsed lla fo slaminA
sretnuh llik dna klats sraeB
erofeb elbapac yllacisyhp neeb reven tsuj dah I tub
.moc.doowyrruF ta 2102 ot kcab gnihcterts sgnidrocer sih dnif nac uoy ,seod eh litnU
.tnetnoc yrev era ew ,ecilA dna em rof sA
.retteb gnihtemos ot deef reh egnahc eh sdnamed :sklat woc s’remraF :SWEN ZYX LENNAHC
detsop dnuof won sngis :rennam evissergga deifinu a ni
,etaneS dna esuoH eht fo noisses tnioj desolc a ni :lufsseccus notgnihsaW no hcram goD .tlas sdeen …eb thgim ti thguoht eh sa dab sa saw ti diaS
.dnim ym ot emac taht gniht tsrif eht dias I ,reh ta gnikooL
.etar yna ta meht fo lla ton ;enasni og ton did ytinamuh ,on ,lleW ?ENASNI
,sregnif ym desu I ,seY
.tsap eht ni draeh ev’I gnos a morf saw enil tsal taht kniht yllautca I
.llew taht lla egnahc eht eldnah t’ndid yllaer yehT
:tub ,esruoc fo flesti efil fo ecnesse eht
.xoF yyxiV yb ”yhcranA“ si
.nruter ot deticxe si dna
,noitautis eht desserdda tnediserP eht
.rellet yrots nrob larutan a tub
.detniona eert dna tnardyh erif yreve
.deracs os erew yeht ,sliat rieht gnisahc s’goD ekil selcric ni nar elpoeP
!GNIOG SI SIHT LLA EREHW SWONK
,taht esaesid egnarts a yb desuac saw ti yas emoS .’gnineppah‘ eht retfa derrucco tahw saw yhcranA
.egnahc hguot a saw ti eerga dluow snamuh tsoM
.rehto eht htiw seog eno esoppus I tub ,erutats ydob ym ot refer ’tsuj‘ ton od I siht nI
.nootrac a ton si siht
.dednepxe neeb sah gnilbbin eot rof ygrene eht ,neht yB
.drow retteb a fo kcal rof ’gnineppah‘
.llew naht retteb tnew ti yas ot dalg ma I
.siht did I sa reh dlot I
.ananab reh tog woC taht fi tuo dnif did reven I tuB
,rehcaet doog a dah I reh dlot I
gnimoc s’tahw wonk
,semit lareves os did I kniht I
.era yeht tahw rof sgniht detpecca evah ,trap tsom eht rof ,elpoeP
.nehw kcab yaw tenretni eht derevocsid ehs nehw retcarahc reh otni nrob saw yyxiV
.yawa nur ehs did roN
eht gnirud htaed hcum hcum saw erehT
.oot taht sekil ecilA .elgrug reh ot netsil ylteiuq dna ,ylleb reh no srae gib ym tup ,reh ot pu eldduc I ,trap ym roF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sdoow eht ni pu yaw nibac a dah ehS
,sdeerb rieht fo snoiton eht htiw og yeht tcaf eht ot refer I siht yB
.GNIRUTCURTSER DNA EVISULCNI LLA WON SI YTINAMUH
sraey net neeb s’tI .nevele ta sweN
.lley ton did ehs ,tiderc reh oT ”.yrgnuh m’I“
,sbmuht elbasoppo htiw sdnah evah ot dnuof neeb evah yeht :sgel kcab no gnidnats
,ozirraC yb uoy rof daer ,xoF yyxiV yb
,aksarbeN ,ahamO fo tuo etaudarg loohcs wal tnecer a
sretnuh dna sraeB .thgif ot wov sgoD
.dloheb ot thgis a
.ereht morf tnew sgnihT
.epacse thguos ew ecalp siht ot saw ti dna
.enoyreve detceffa ,ssel ro erom
.hcum yrev nerdlihc ruo dna
.stiB dna slebbiK
.retteb eht rof saw siht kniht I ,eno gnieB
.ytrap lacitilop nwo rieht detrats yllautca yehT
yehT‘ ,yas stac yella yb dessap sromur
ylurt si namuh dekan a
.hgual doog a rof tsuj swen eht hctaw I dna ecilA .won
.doots I ,egac eht fo tuo gnilwarC
.dah eb ot ngised a saw ylurt ereht fi ,ngised yb saw siht spahreP
.ti fo trap a eb ot esufer dna ,dniheb yhcrana eht tfel eW
.sdoow eht morf elpoep gninnab
.oot ti ees dluow uoy ,weiv fo tniop ruo morf efil ta kool ot erew uoy fi tub ,tnemetats yvaeh yrev yrev a si taht wonk I ,seY
.tep remrof a ot netsil ynam toN
,ssenyls nwo ym evah I ,xoF a gnieB
yrots s’yadoT dna
.reh htiw evol ni hcum yrev dna
,wonk won I tahw gniwonK
.xoF cenneF a eb syawla lliw I
.xoF cenneF a ma I .tep citoxe na saw I ,nageb ’yhcrana‘ eht nehW
.truoc eht ni
”,uoy ot kaeps ot elba eb ot dehsiw syawla evah I“
.ylisae os sgniht krow sdnah wen ym gnihctaw tsuj
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,kcab dellac ehs ’?ereht
?evah yeht did eciohc tahW
sbur ymmut em evig ot deliaf reven ehS
sepoh eht ni stluser noitanimaxe rab sih gnitiawa ylsuoixna
.sregnif ym fo ffo gge eht dekcil dna kcab delims I
,em ot emac ehs nehw dna
.dekan dnuora klaw yltneuqerf htob ew erehw ,sdoow eht ni ylippah etiuq evil dna nibac eht tfel reven eW
.peelsa llaf ot yaw taerg a s’tI
”yhcranA“ saw sihT
.sananab yrt ot stnaW
.lrig a dna yob a ,stik lufrednow owt evah eW
,gnitirw siht ni od ot nrows evah I hcihw ,tsenoh eb ot ma I fI
?pu dewercs os si taht dlrow a lortnoc ot yrt yhw …tsuj s’ti
ehT‘ ,yas stac yella yb dessap sromur :gnidih fo tuo emoc staC )spoonS taC ykaenS yb yrots( .mehyam latot ti gnillac
.xofyyxiv :si etisbew reh ,seirots reh ekil uoy fI
.dlrow eht gnillortnoc ot bmilc eht nugeb evah staC
emoc sah emit
.tnereffid gnieb ot nekat lla evah sgoD ehT
,ruf on evah yehT
.nootrac a saw ti ;stcaf ecaf s’tel tub ,eivom nootrac taht ni cenneF eht htiw did yensiD tahw wonk I ,seY
.tsafkaerb em evag dna ni em koot ehS
.eerf si gnidaer eht erehw moc.xofyyxiv
.em dniheb pu tes ti dah ehS
.srevol emaceb ew retfa saw siht ,esruoc fO
,pu em depoocs ecilA ,nageb ti nehW
toof reh nopu decnuop I nehw
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
:NOITIDE GOD – SWEN X LENNAHC .won
,god.ecioveht ta
,gnorw em teg t’nod esaelP .semitemos
aciremA htroN ssorca snoitnevnoc yrruf ta
,hcae evol ew ,seY
.yralubacov ym fo ssenetelpmoc eht ta dezama saw ehS
,poop ,eep llits seibab esoht dna :gnirpsffo derb ssorc gnivah era snamuH .gniklat pots t’now yeht su pleh doG dna ,sbmuht elbasoppo htiw sdnah evah ot dnuof neeb evah yeht :sgel kcab no gnidnats llits snoitpircsed lla fo slaminA .etisbew ruo tisiv esaelp snoitcerid roF .elpoep yb devres dna sraeb yb nur won sbup lareves gnimialcorp detsop dnuof won sngis :rennam evissap ylbaifinu a ni
.gniklat pots t’now yeht su pleh doG dna
’.dlrow eht revo ekat ot
tae ot decrof :egac god remrof ni pu dekcol
.degnahc slamina eht nehw emit a saw tI .yhcranA
.deneppah tahw dellac yeht tahw s’tahT .yhcranA
noitcudorp oidua dna gnitca eciov ni slenap thguat ozirraC ,loohcs wal ot roirP
.snoitcaretni eht hctaw ot nuf s’ti dna won ti gnikrow slamina dna elpoep fo erutxim a evah yehT
.sekacnap yrrebeulb dna ,sgge htob su edam ehS
rehctac god remroF
,htob meht evol llits I tub ,yllis dnuos thgim tI .gnilbbin eot dna sbur ymmut …em ot netsiL
.nugtohs a htiw demra saw ehs
.nikpan a dna slisnetu esu ot woh nrael ot evah dluow I em gnillet ,delims ehs dna
s’ohW‘ .eman reh tuo dellac I ,thguoht tuohtiW
’.ti htiw od ot gnihton tnaw dna
.rood eht tuo saw dna ,gab yrrac reh ni em deffuts
dlrow eritne ehT
.seot reh no delbbin dna
:gnidih otni og staC .noitca rof ssol a ta ytiruceS