.saw’t tahw llet t’ndluoc I
,me‘ raeh ot tog I ssel xob-lived ’lo yrettalc a morf elddif tneced a wonk ’ndluow I
.krow ot pu nrut t’nid eh ,’ninrom enO“ ”.t’nsaw eh lliT“
,mih fo skool eht yb ,ereh ni gnipeels saW
.thgindim tsap no niyrrac dna nipeew dna nirelloh saw eh diaS
,dnuora skool knuks dlo ehT
.nepo kaerc rood eht raeh I tub ,kcalb hctip s’tI
.eciton ylerab uoy gnorts os si smossolb eht fo llems eht tub
,si siht fo lla tluaf esohw
.knuks eht
nam llat-oot eht saw ,ees dluoc I lla ,d’ees adluoc yeht llA
edistuo dnal tnereffid
.noitcerid gnorw eht nrut ot tuoba neeb t’ndah etuor sih fi moor letom a erahs ot dereffo adluow
.tneserp eht otni kcab flesmih sknilb knuks ehT ”…yhW“
.rehtaef siht tog I woh s’tahT .haey oS
.nihton yas t’nod yoB ynnhoJ“
”.noitseuq ni wollef eht wonk I kniht t’nod I“ ,boj a rof raeh annaw t’nod yeht sgniht elpoep llet ot gnivah ot desu s’eh llet dluoc uoy erehw eciov adnik eht ,syas tacbob eht ”,ris ,hU“ ”.kcen
”,taht yb naem I tahw flesim wonk
.kaerb a nevig teg I
dniw eltneg a tsuj
,gnihtemos yas eciov s’knuks eht raeh I kniht I
,floWcaM boR yb
,spahrep teknirt llams emos ,liated lausunu dna wen a eciton uoY
.pu ti dekcip evah t’ndluohs I
.thgil eht tsap sevom ti nehw dlog dna elprup dna neerg lla sremmihs ti tub
ro doow atuo fo daets
,gnidloh saw eh eno eht ekil toN
.mrots eht tub edistuo gnihton s’ereht hguoht
,dexif llimdniw eht tig nac uoy erofa yrd seog llew eht fi od ’nog er’uoy tahw tuob
,lufituaeb nmaddog os saw tI .uoy ’nihctaw
.senim nwod desolc eht at’pu del taht skcart meht dessorc ti erehw ,daor trac dlo eht no tuo nees neeb d’eh dias emos
:gniht emas eht gnikniht eerht lla er’ew wonk ot
’deksa ydobon ,on‘ syas su fo eno fi
”.niaga mih ees reven ydobon t’niD“ ”.yoB
…tsuj tI .ti dehcuot evah t’ndluohs I
.taht naht ti tuoba erom yna wonk t’nod I tub
.stoob foorpretaw gib dna sllarevo
,sworc fo kcolf taerg a si ssenkrad eht ,wonk I gniht txeN“
.pots sub a eb ot tuo denrut hcihw ,ees dluoc I retlehs ylno eht rof detnirps I oS
,esion ’nihceercs elbirroh ythgimla na s’ereht ylneddus
”.nmad a htrow elddif eht yalp n’dluoc yoB ynnhoJ“ syas eh dna—
.ereht eb athguo taht eno eht morf
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sworc fo lluf ylneddus si ssenkrad eht fI
”.mih dessik eh dnA“
,erom yas ot tuoba s’eh kniht I ”.rehtaef siht si
”?nuh ereht thgirla uoY“
tpecxe …xaler lla ew dna
.klat ot nwod tis uoy
,emoH ykcutneK dlO yM eb ot desop’s saw ’nihceercs taht gnicnuonna s’eh
,sraor evots eht ni erif eht dna rekcilf sthgil ehT
,gnorw derellaws uoy yeksihw eht no gnikohc deppots dna ecnalab rey thguac uoy emit eht yb dna
.rehtaef a si tfel ecart ylnO
?thgir ,ezeerf ll’yeht ro retlehs deen ti rof gnitiaw elpoep neht ,etal si sub eht dna ni dewons steg daor eht fI
.erehwon fo tuo ,pu swolb mrotsrednuht a retal setunim neetfif toN
.nwot deppiks eh erofa ,oga sraey ,taht denwap d’aP sih ,esac on evah t’ndiD
,rof tnaem saw ecalp eht tahw ton s’taht fi nevE
.sseug ot dah I fi revird feiler a ylbaborp ,tacbob ,mrofinu enil sub a ni yuG
,ecaf ym ni gnimaercs ,erehwyreve tuo gnitsrub
yrots eht raeh ot tnaw t’ndid ew llet t’nac rehtie knuks ehT ”!yawyna ,trap tnatropmi eht s’rehtaef ehT
.t’ndluoc I nehw gnikihhctih dna me droffa dluoc I nehw sessub ecnatsid gnol gnihctac saw I oS
yeht erehw thgir
,knurd s’eh kniht I tsrif tA
”?stseuqer yna evah ydobyna did dna
.tnereffid dekool eH
s’ereht ,won no dessap s’niar ehT
,rab eht drawot snrut eh oS
.mirb eht ni kcuts rehtaef s’worc a htiw tah pu taeb a dna ,elbats a atuo ti elots eh ekil dekool taht ohcnop kcalb ydeggar ,ytrid a gniraew s’eH
hguone doog rey n’fi em loof ylborp dluoc uoy neht neve dna
.enog er’sworc eht ,no kcab emac sthgil eht emit eht yB“ .sevae leets detagurroc eht rednu gnimmuh
.flessih ’o erus erom ,redrah ,rellaT
,moolb ni seirrebkcalb fo elgnat a atni ’nillaf ekil saW
.nepo nwolb atsum srood eht ezilaer I dna
,detfut si pot eht ta snip eht dnA
seirots neewollaH gnidaer er’ew keew siht dna
.taht mih evig ll’I ,thgirla ,dah eh hcihW
,evots eht revo depoots er’yehT
tog I raef eht lla dnoces a rof dna
.si taht ohw wonk ot desoppus er’ew ekiL
dekcik ro tuo detuohs ro tuo dehgual teg d’eh retal r’renooS
,dniw ythgimla neddus a saw ereht nehW
ti gnikat ton taht
,dias I ekiL“ ,sgurhs knuks eht
,su fo enon htiw eltneg tnia dlrow eht swonk dog ,esruoc a ,esneffo oN
.mrots eht morf ni dekcud sklof nehw pu ekow tog dna
tuoba saw eh ekil yltcaxe ,syas eh ”,yrots ym hsinif attog tsuj ,ma’am ,enif sej eb ll’I“
.ereht su ees ot desirprus s’eh ekil
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer dna nettirw
.ot tog t’nod uoy ,enon yrrow t’nod ,hO“
eht“ ,niaga su eciton ot smees ,elttil a ,pu stis eh
,rab eht yb ’nirewoc ,yob ynnhoJ ot revo dedilg eH .ni niwolb
s’tahT .elttil a ,seod evots eht tuB
,hcihw ,ereht ni sklof rehto s’ereht dna ,ni teg I
,hctap atamot eht atuo stsucol ’nipeews tuob ,hsurb ’niraelc ’tuob nikniht er’uoY
.enog s’knuks eht ees ot thgil hguone tsuj
.meht emalb t’nod I dna
”.niaga esuoH ekuJ eht atni sklaw eh thgin eht lliT“
s’ti dnA .ezeerf su fo eerht llA
krow morf ’nihca pots kcab rey ekam ot owt r’yeksihw a kcab kconk ot ’niyrt sej rey nehw ,ti detcepxe tsael allef a nehw thgin yreve dnA .esuoH ekuJ eht ta pu nrut d’yoB ynnhoJ oS“
”?lufituaeb saw ti dias uoy tuB“
!ti rof ksa t’ndid dna
.dah eb ot krow saw ereht nisuoc a morf egassem a dah d’I ,s’regnirrA .tS drawot pu teg ot gniyrt saw I
gnidneterp si ro
ylthgir I kniht t’noD“
?ti tuoba ksa uoy dluohS .rehtaef a ekil
”,dluow eh dehsiw ylraed lla ew sa hcum
,ekil ,stnemom esoht fo eno
,emoh yaw ruoy no teg uoy erofa
.tuo og sthgil eht tub
.ees nac I gnihtyna no desucof tnia seye sih dna
.’nihtyna tsom ees ot krad oot sawT
.ecalp ni yltaen s’rebif elttil yreve dna wen dna yssolg s’eno siht
.esop’s I knird a flessih teg ot
,seciov worc atuo elddif a edam
,won ,flesmih no ni deldduh s’eH
.foor dna swodniw eht selttar ti taht hguone esolc ,sdnuos rednuhT
,draeh reve d’enoyna reyalp elddif nmad tseb eht eb d’eh ,gnorw lla su evorp d’eh yad eno taht nwod n’pu raews d’eh ,tuo
,niyrt mih pots t’ndiD“
.laiceps nihtemos s’gniht siht llet nac I neve tuB
.no pirg htaed a tog llits s’eh rehtaef eht fo egnirf delggardeb eht hguorht evots ninrub eht otni serats knuks dlo ehT
.rehtegot ’nignis lla ,riohc lepsog a dah sworc
,gninthgil eht tsniaga deniltuo
.mih ni terref ro retto emos tog ebyam ,ynwarcs ,knuks dlo na si renroc eht ni revo nehT
.rehtaef worc a tuo sdloh eh dna
.eno tnereffid a s’tI .eno siht ton s’ti ,oN ?tahW
.gnol reven t’nerew’t tub ,thgin ot thgin morf reffid
.tesolc s’apmarg rey morf ekil
deificeps adluohs I ,tog ev’I eno siht TON si hcihw—gnidloh s’eh rehtaef eht ta serats eh oS
.seiceps ot sa sseug neve ot hguone ees dluoc me fo enon eveileb t’nod I tub
thgir ,tsewhtron eht atuo ,uoy revo nwod emoc dniw fo tsalb dloc taht gnivah ekil saw tI .rehtien daeh ym atuo ti teg ot elba eb reven t’now I tuB .ti fo eton a eltsihw ron muh ’ndluoC
.niog ti teg ot gniyrt
.yrruh ot gniyrt s’eh ekil seunitnoc eH
.nwod tis dna emoh teg yllanif uoy dna ,truh teef ruoy dna ,eros si kcab ruoy dna ,yad lla gniklaw neeb ev’uoy nehw ekiL .deveiler dnA
.ruopnwod a ni kcud ot ecalp doog a er’yeht
”.srehtaef delggardeb ekil
?pu mih elir annog taht si
.lleh ot lla ’nimaercs dna ’nippalf dna ’niwac ,yaw hcihw yreve ’nirettacs
,tsevrah retfa ,nroc yrd a dleif a tsap ’niklaw ekil saW .stih niar eht erofeb
.nac yeht sa tsaf rood noitats sub eht tuo ruop ot gniyrt
.seriw noisnet hgih evil ekil ,me ot tes steg neve ti erof nireviuq ydaerla si sgnirts dna
,llew ,dnuorg eht gnihcuot t’nerew teef sih ebyam taht hguone llat
.elddif taht tog eh erehw ksa ot nixif m’I os ,ydobon ot drow a dias tnia llits eh
,ekil ydaetsnu ,teef sih ot steg knuks eht
,mih ref tuo eye na tpek ot tnaem eW“
nu gnuoy a saw uoy nehw morf senut ’lo tub gnihton ’nivah dna
”.tuo tnew sthgil eht lla dna
.tsrif ta mih ezingocer t’ndid thgin taht ereht sallef weF
rehtiE .llat ooT .nam llat A
taht ’nikniht rebmemer I
”edihC htoD mryW gnirennuhC eht dnA“
thgin eht ni tuo eb thgim revetahw ffo draw ot
ti tnaw t’nod ohw
”doog on seod ti taht ton
”!?rehtaef siht tog I woh wonk annaw uoY“
,nogard a ro noil a ro flow a saw ti mialc me draeh I .txen deneppah tahw sa eerga t’nod kloF“
,nihc sih rednu sdnah htob ni dehctulc rehtaef eht
eh nees I dna ,sredluohs sih revo kcab ohcnop eht sworht
,sredluohs sih sehcnuh
,wodniw a morf tuo ’nikool ekil saw tI
,thgilerif otni ,resolc semoc eH
ynnhoJ s’oS .nam llat eht s’oS
.rehsawyllug laer A
em ot rucco t’ndid
,’ninnur dna ’nirelloh s’esuoh ekuj eht ni enoyrevE
”!oS“ .emit siht krow t’ndiD
,ffo foor eht skconk duolc lennuf on
.foor eht gnizeeuqs dna swodniw eht gnilttar pots ot rednuht fo elbmur a rof stiaw ,sesuap eH
.evots eht fo edis rehto eht no dnats ot ediced I os htob s’eh kniht I neht dna
”.noitibihorP s’eh ekil yoB ynnhoJ togrof s’ydobyreve dna sthgin ytrof n’syad ytrof neeb s’ti wonk uoy gniht txen dna
.derit dna dlo skool tsuj eh ,eromyna knurd kool t’nod eh dna
.ehtaerb’t neve derad fo eno a ton ,tnelis daed saw ti dnA
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,elfir ’lo a no tenoyab a ekil ,dne eht ta prahs skool wob ehT
,yawrood eht ta seralg eH
.ssenisub eht ’niyalp ta hguone dab ro
.sit‘ woh wonk uoy tuB
a gniees dna ,dniw eht ni nignab si srettuhs eht nehw
ees uoy srehtaef yna evael uoY ?enog m’I fi dna
,war uoy eparcs snroht
flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
”.thgin txen eht kcab syawla saw eh tuB
,dias I ekil ,ti ot gnitteg m’I
.won yb ,kcab sraey wef a saw sihT
?mih htiw ereh ni kcuts er’ew elihW
,erif eht revo dehcnuh stis dna hcneb eht revo spets knuks dlo eht dna
,denoihsaf-dlo ,stoob dna sresuort ’nikool-ddo emos tsuj ,trihs on tog tnia
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
?ezeerb dloc dliw a s’ereht fI
,mih erofa aP sih ekil nwot deppiks dna niart a deppoh d’eh thguoht emos ,erehwemos hctid a ni revognah naem a ffo nipeels saw eh thguoht emoS .t’nia eh tub ,elddif ’lo eht neve ,ereht llits si sgniht na sehtolc sih lla ,kcahs sih kcehc ot og salleF
hguoht rehton’t tsniag eno eltsur sklats daed eht lla gniraeh dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,thgin tilrednuht kcalb eht ta wodniw eht tuo gnikool si ecaf sih ,thgiarts dormar si kcab siH
,yug emosdnah ,drazil denroH
.dehs elohw eht skcor ti drah os stih dniw fo tsug a ylnedduS
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
flesmih rohtua eht yb daer ,floWcaM boR yb ”edihC htoD mryW gnirennuhC eht dnA“ :yojne esaelP   .goD fo tsohG eht no
eh edisni spets elpuoc a steg eh nehw dnA
.laocrahc eht depiws s’ydobemos yllausu hguoht ,sevots laocrahc elttil tog yeht dna
”.sdaeh rieht ’nirevoc dna selbat eht rednu ’nivid
noitatneserp neewollaH laiceps a fo trap sa
’.etal oot s’ti erofeb‘ htiw ecnetnes taht hsinif ot
.rekcurt a yb nwodnus retfa tsuj ffo deppord tog I
a s’ti ,ssenkrad tnia ssenkrad eht neht dnA
,elttil a ,kcab selpmurc knuks ehT
”.enon dnuorg eht hcuot t’nod teef sih ro ,taht
fi ekil ,sworc fo ssem elohw a ekil dnuos ot detratS
,nac yeht sa em morf raf sa tis htob yeht tuB
’?yllanif‘ eb dluoc
,foor eht no lenap ralos a ffo nur taht sthgil tog yehT
.erac t’nseod eh esuac
.wap sih ni elddif sih dna sgel sih txiwt liat sih htiw emoh ffo yrrucs d’eh neht
.tcatnoc eye ekam ton dna tuhs htuom ym peek ot woh wonk ot hguone gnol sliar eht dna sessub eht gnidir neeb d’I tsuj s’ti
”.efil ym lla ni diarf eros os neeb reven tnia I tub
krad eht ni tuo tsol gnieb ekil saw tI
.yrots detacilpmoc a s’ti ,lleW
,ssenkrad krad-ssel fo erauqs a was I“
dna revird eht ot gnihtemos syas tacbob eht tub ,eraf a rof yenom evah t’nod I .semoc sub eht nehw ,nac yeht sa tsaf draob yehT
,nwod sllaw eht spir odanrot on tub
ohcnop eht rednu ,nees osla I tuB
.worruf sworb s’nosib eht
?won dnoces yna ,tuo og sthgil eht fi ...ebyam tpecxE
’?em dnif‘ eb dluoc ti ekil sdnuos
”.uoy no taht hsiw d’I taht toN .fles nwo ruoy ref ti raeh ot evah d’uoY
.dlihc a gniteiuq s’ehs ekiL .syas nosib eht
,enim laoc a ni thgindim sa ,kcalb si ydob ehT
”.atesu syawla eh ekil ,sgnirts ot wob stes dna roolf eht fo retnec eht ot sreggaws tsuJ
,god.ecioveht ta
.su dewohs erus d’eh ekil
,tsae ffo ,gninthgil tnatsid era mrots eht fo sniamer ylnO
deneppah ti evorp ot tog I llA“
?setats eiriarp eht ni tuo sub a thguac reve ev’uoy fi onnud I ,woN
.detacilpmoc s’ti
.onnud I ,noitpo na saw
.ta kool ot mih ’niwonk ton ref enon ay emalb n’dluoW“
,haey ,tuoba neht thgir gnihtemos dias ev’dluow I ,ekatpu eht no rekciuq neeb d’I fI
.deyalp eh saw ti tahw ay llet ’ndluoc I“
”.ria eht atni pu mih thguac eh
si yrots s’yadoT
”.no seye dial reve I elddif nikool-tseicnaf eht ’niyrrac s’eh
,kcis s’eh kniht I neht dna
,sworc fo toir gnihtirw
tacbob eht ro nosib eht ta kool neve ot evah t’nod I erehw
,tacbob eht syas ”,I“ ”.sgnirts
.ni emoc ezeerb a leef I
…d’ydobemos ekil rO
dluow htiw pu tup tog eh gnol woH“
.sretniw emos teg yeht sdrazzilb eht fo tnuocca no ,skcahs eseht ni era spots sub eht tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.esuoh ekuj eht ta enituor lausu sih naht tnereffid on dnuos t’nid taht woh tuoba sekoj emos erew ereht sseuG
.lenap ralos eht tuoba aydloT .no kcab emac t’nod sthgil ehT
,nam llat a fo etteuohlis eht ees owt rehto eht fo rehtie fi dna
,niaga ti raeh reven t’nod I yarp I dnA .lufituaeb oS“
,nosib ,ydal redlO :lausunu ton
.gnihtyna yas t’nod yeht
”edihC htoD mryW gnirennuhC eht dnA“ ni ,thginot
sregnarts fo puorg a ta ecnamrofrep ssa-elohw a pu strats dna ni segrab enoemos nehw laed dab a si erus
?nepo mals rood eht raeh uoy fI
.desseug adluow I naht eciov retfos a tog ehS
.’niyalp dehsinif yoB ynnhoJ ,oS“
,thgindim tsap sruoh elpuoc a n’erom tsal ot mees reven
,ecnis reve ti deirrac ev’I
.ereht ’nidnats nam a s’ereht dnA
,pu uoy wollaws selbmarb
”.ris ,taht yb naem uoy tahw wonk I kniht t’nod“
.dniw on tnia ereht
…uoy llet dluow yeht taht si neppah nac taht tsrow eht yleruS
.flesim ,rehsilop-eriw on m’I“
,olleh yas uoy ,dneirf dlo na teem uoY .oiranecs A  ..egap
.yalp atesu elcnu sih elddif ’lo pu taeb eht htiw esuoh ekuj eht ta pu wohs d’eh ,thgin yrevE“
.edistuo sub eht rof tiaw eW
.mih pots ot etal oot saw ti desseug I nehw saw hcihw
,naem dennirg eh dna ,wols dewob eh dnA
.neeb eh erehw ydobon llet t’nod ,ydobon teerg t’noD
.goD fO tsohG ehT dellac
.kcen eht yb dnuor ti deirrac sej yoB ynnhoJ
.ot gninetsil saw I elddif a erew ti erus saw I ssel
”,denetsil I regnol eht ,si gniht ylno ehT“
”edihC htoD mryW gnirennuhC eht dnA“ saw sihT     .eil
:cificeps laer steg
.ekil evislupmoc ,enips eht nwod dna pu gninnur bmuht eno
.gnikaeps si eh n’erom ,won gnilworg s’knukS ehT
.skeew elpuoc a ref