.tcefrep si aedi nA
,regniR  ratS sa nwonk osla ,tsreG noraA sa nwonk osla ,xoF rolyaT yb
saw sihT     .em evigroF
noitcefrep tcejbus ot
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
gnieb rehto eno ylno fi dnA
,noitaerc ni niap si erehT
,noitcefrepmi nwo ym nodrap esaelP
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,tuc ,nekorb ,nrohs
,htob su ot esimorp I
,relevart wollef ruoy
.noitcefrepmi detpecca ev'I
,htgnerts htiw enoemoS
.lliks dna ,ecneiliser
ti gnikees elbatrofmoc leef ll'uoy ,tra sih ni detseretni er'uoy fi sepoh ohw
.detaerc eb yam uoy taht
.tsum I tuB  ?I dluoc woH
.enitsirp si aedi nA  .lliw I wonk I
.ecnetsixe fo trap a si noitcurtseD   yojne esaelP
,ylesicerp ,evah ton od I
,ytiniffA ruF ,ykS eulB
si ti ynoga tahw tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.noitcurtsed naht htaed retaerg a si nettogrof eb oT
regniR_ratS ta dnuof eb ll'eH .tuo
,eb ton dluow uoy taht
.enola dnim ym dna
.thguoht elttil tcefrep
.dnats I erehw ytilaer emas eht ni eb ot reve si ti fi ,derettahs dna
,dnim ym morf tpecxe
,thguoht elttil tcefrep
.uoy yb thgir od llahs I
,uohsneguuY yb uoy rof daer ,xoF rolyaT yb
.ma I naht retteb enoemos ot emoc dah uoy ylno fI
,su sdnatsrednu dna
.tsulrednaW fo floW
.noitalsnart ni ti niur lliw I taht yrrow a
floWcaM boR si sihT
,rettiwT gnidulcni smroftalp no
,enutrofsim tahw tuB
.tra ym yortsed ot tnaw ton od I
.dezilaer eb tsum ti tuB
,uoy yortsed llahs I  .yrt ot
..tsulrednaW fo floW
.noitcurtsed osla si ti esuaceb
,uohsneguuY yb daeR .yrruFoS dna
su secneirepxe noitaerc fo lla ni
.dedeeccus evah lliw ew
,”noitcurtseD sI erehT ,nehT dnA"
,dekcarc eb tsum tpecnoC
.noitazilaer fo erutrot eht ot
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot