”?sevlesruo naht siht sa hcus weiv a hcus tnemelpmoc ot stcejbus retteb tahw dnA“
.segatniv reroop sih ffo gnilles si
”.ereh noitarepsed fo sllems su fo eno ylnO“
.kniht I ,swal evissergorp
.esolc a ot semoc yrasrevinna htruof ruo nehw mraw dna ecin su gnipeek dna
,pu snetfos tiK yhw nosaer eht si eniw eht tcepsus I
”.ti tuoba yrrow t’noD
”.rehtie t’nod uoy erus ekam ll’I
”.dnik ruoy rof emit on evah I .ot ees ot sremotsuc gniyap evah I ,won yawA“
”?anrevat eht ta eta ew emit taht tuoba tahw ,lleW“
,rehtegot emoh reggats eW
ria hserf eht yojne ot sreknird rof selbat wef derettacs eht ,edistuO .daeha smool
.spuc ruo llifer ot tnirps a ta elbat ruo ot revo gnimoc
,naelc skool noitcelfer yM
.wonk I .thgirla ,tniop eht ruobal ot evah t’nod uoy ,nareiK“
,enim sa elyts dna tif emas eht fo tekcaj eulb elap a detceles s’eH
,emit ot emit morf ,yvne ot larutan si ti dna
.sessam eht fo dnim eht egnahc lliw ohw xof eht rof em ot kool ot ton thguo uoY“
.rood eht hguorht thgiarts deppets eW“
,remraf eniw lacol a erehw ,teerts eht gnola sllats eht fo eno ot gnola em sgut tiK
ekat nac I hcihw
”.esrow hcum enog ev’dluoc tI .og mih tel I tub
,tsirw ym ssorca pals a flesym nrae dna ,hctorc ym ta barg I
,rehtegot spuc ruo kcilc eW ”.uoy htiw
”.edisni eht no selbat on evah ew diarfa m’I“
”.hguone naht erom ylbaborp s’tahT“ .syas tiK ”,nareiK“
.xofnogarD reppad eht
.slepal ym morf ruf ffo gnihsurb dna ralloc ym pu gninrut ,hgis I
.rehtegot emac ew fi ni gniog su tneverp d’yeht wenk I
,semitemos tub ,ocaC htiw ton ebyaM“
.smra sih gnidlof elihw snworf lesaew yM
.stnemom elttil eseht yojne od I esuaceB
tsuj t’nseod gnir ehT
.ssalg eniw ym ni elzzum ym yrub dna ,kcab og srae ym leef I ”...nareiK“
,dnatsrednu seod yllautca eh gnihtemos tuoba klat tiK gniraeh yojne I tuB
,yppah uoy ekam lliw ffo yad a gnikat taht dlot m’I fi dnA
,yad eno ereh esuoh a thguob ew fi ynnuf ylralucitrap eb ti t’ndluow dna
-esilaer t’nod uoy ebyam ,em esucxE“
,tuo ehtaerb I ”.netsil ,tiK“
naem I ...naem I ...ot uoy tnaw t’ndid I“
.enoyna nopu hsiw d’I gnihtemos ton s’tI
nwod ekat yeht erofeb
.em morf ssalg eniw ym gnikat daetsni
”,thgirla ,xof ,thgirlA“
”?pam ym no ti tniop uoy nac
”.ti denoitnem evah thgim ...I“
.yltfos sffup erah ehT
.ecnalg tsal a rof rorrim ym ot nrut I
.eton tsekrad eht no kcams thgir sdnal daetsni tub
.level eye ym ta repap pu-dellor a sdloh eH
.noziroh eht sdrawot ezag I elihw kaeps lesaew eht gnittel ,noitnetta yna mih yap t’nod I
.ereh spets ym hctaw ot evah I tuB
.gninrom siht tluciffid tib a neeb evah I ebyaM
.teiuq dna tnatiseh ,wols s’ti ,gnihtemos syas yllanif eh nehW
gnihton s’ereht taht meht wohs tsrif ot evah uoy ,taht teg ot dnA
,ti tuoba yrrow ot evah ton
.mra sih gnikat ,yaw eht dael mih tel I
”.rehtorb ’sieR ekuD htiw pu eussi eht ekat nac uoY“
”.tsael ta ,yas ll’eh sseug I tahw s’tahT
.ti ssik I nehw ylevol os sleef taht ruf tfos eht ,srae sih dniheB
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,meht naht rehto elpoep rof enod si taht doog eht lla ot luftneser ro dnilB
”.oot ,uoy yojne ot tnaw I“
,hguoht doom ym no pu skcip eH
.noob tsellams eht
.ecniw mih gnikam ,oot nethgit sreksihw sih dnuora pirg yM
.sremmats eh ”?otiV ,hO ...hO“
.ti od ot evah ton od ohw esoht
O“ ”?etalocohc dnA“
”,taht yojne did I“
.srevlis dna sreppoc ni enutrof llams a gnoma eltsen ot retaw eht otni ti skcilf dna ,ti sessik
.lareneg ni pohs eeffoc eht ot erutseg I ”...siht
.yllacitnarf sdon ,pihw eht diova ot yas nac eh gnihtyna rof etarepsed ,ocaC
”.em htiw tsenoh neeb ev’dluoc uoY“
?gnorw od I did tahW“
”.rehtegot nuf gnivah su fo yaw eht ni teg ti tel t’now I hguoht neve ,semitemos noinipo ruoy deen I dna ,uoy evol I
lla dna ,oot ettorag eht sekat osla eH
.uoy morf hcum oot deksa I semit esoht rof ezigolopa em teL“
.nrobbuts si erah eht tub ,tca eht pu speek lesaew ehT
”.etsahc gnieb fo gninaem wen elohw a uoy hcaet ll’I ,steehsdeb s’rolias a ekil llems uoy esuaceb ereht ni teg t’nod ew fI
,sresuort eulb krad
”?taht saw tahW“ .seod tiK tub
”.keew a naht erom rof tuohtiw og ylbissop dluoc uoy fi sA“
”?siht s’tahw nehT“
.txen ruo rof tiaw t’nac I
.tiK ,em srehtob taht uoy htiw gnieb ton s’tI“ .elbmum I
”.nwo ym no ti fo erac koot I oS
.seunitnoc tac eht
,gnippis sa syas eh ”,ecin os s’ti ,hO“ ”.ecin si sihT“
”?won otni flesmih nettog eh sah tahw ...tahW“
”.mih raen dewolla ton m’I“ ”.mih
,nediw seye s’erah eht sekam stsil ruo no srelggums muipo tnenimorp tsom eht fo eno fo eman eht fo noitnem ehT .mih llet I
.mih ot ti dnah dna
.em rof erusaem a tuo gniruop elihw ,syas eh
.ruf etihw fo raelc s’ti erus gnikam
,ereh elbat nwo ym evah I nehw luftegrof tsom ym ta ma I“
”,siht gnikat m’I“ ”?I nac
.erom neve ralloc sih no pirg ym nethgit I elihw
.tiartrop a sa prahs s’eH
,regnif yreve ylraen no dlog
.tnemhsilbatse eht evael ew ,stes nus eht ecnO
”.thginot tnecs ruoy edih ot uoy rof ecalp ecin a dnif ll’I esimorp I
,etuor ruo gnola azalp a ta sehcneb eht fo eno tuo stniop eH
”-hcni na uoy evig nac I“
”.taht seod ydobon dnA .em tcepser
”.yad ym deniur ti
.noisiv ym ssorca sevom edahs A
.ocaC ,tca eht tiuQ“
,dlrow riafnu na tsniaga egarevel sa noitisop ym esu ot em stnaw eh fi tuB
”,won litnu enif yltcefrep deganam ev’uoY“
,yaw ym skool erah ehT
.eniw eht ta gnippis ,mih llet I
.retniw tsal denepo ti ecnis nwot fo edis htron eht no revo anafaK eht ot og ot detnaw sah eH .naorg I ”,wonk I“
.daetsni ,taht yrt
.noitasrevnoc eht fo doom eht daer ot gniyrt ylwols ,ksa I ”?ecI“
.shgis neht ,em ot ssorca skool tiK
.gel sih fo kcab eht tsniaga ekorts liat ym tel I
.semitemos htiw laed ot evah I sruetama eht ,hO
seye ruoy ni erised etarepsed eht gnieeS
.rood eht ta su steem elzzum sih dnuora ruf gniyerg htiw erah yknal A
”?tnaw uoy od tahW“
...fo stnih ti esuaceb ,etadimitni ot tnaem s’tI
.roliat nwo s’truoc eht yb tif ym ot deroliat era hcihw stnap dna
.elims a htiw dnopser I ”,tiK ,yrrow t’noD“
.srevol lufepoh morf snioc sward
.og ew taht detsisni uoy tub ,ereht emoclew t’nsaw I wenk uoy ,si tniop ehT“
.rethgit ralloc sih pirg I tub ,daeh sih sekahs erah ehT
,ti ot txen debircsni eman sih htiw gnir esimorp a
”?ti t’ndid ,llew tnew tahT .anevaR ot ssorca pirt taht no em koot uoy
.t’nsi mih fo tnecs eht tub ,deyonna kool yam eH
”...ereh t’nsaw I fi htaed ot flesruoy krow d’uoY“ .selffins eH
.noitceffa fo syalpsid cilbup no nwod kool t’nod
...tahw uoy llet reven ot esimorp I dnA“
”?od uoY“ .tiK si sa
,etalocohc toh fo puc ym nevig neeb ev’I dna ,detaes er’ew ecnO
.tuo ti ecnalab ,ti stup eh sa
?em ot netsil ll’eh kniht uoy sekam tahW“
,saw eeffoc sih ecin woh tuoba em llet ot stnaw yllaer eh llet nac I
,dnekeew a spahreP
,su fo dloh gnikat eniw eht
”.tuo gniog ekilsid I taht emahs fo tuo ton s’ti llew yltcefrep wonk uoY“
,kcaba nekat s’eH
.retsaf ehtaerb ot strats eh taht hguone gnol tsuj rof ezag sih dloh I
.ecin eb ll’ti kniht I“ .syas eh
.eert kao detnuts a morf edahs delppad eht yb derevoc
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”?ereh hcni na em evig ...tsuj uoy naC
.niaga roolf eht ot nwod skool eh neht tub
”...eb llits d’uoy tcepxe t’ndid I
”?yadretsey nrob saw I kniht uoy oD“
”,leef uoy tahw ot retteb netsil ll’I esimorp I dnA“
”?yadot elbasopsid eb d’uoy enoyna llet uoy diD“
.lesaew ym thguorb ti yoj hcum woh morf gnigduj
...tcatnoc a tsuj ,tiK ,gnihton s’tI“
”,staps ruoy no tup ,oS“
.doohruobhgien reporp yrev siht ni
,hcae spuc wef a retfA
,sreetavirp larom fo hcnub a dna
dedroffa era sredistuo emos revenehw tnemnrevog rieht dna ecnirP rieht tuoba rettum ll’yeht
,gnir ybur ym ot ,enim morf gniyarts seye sih ees nac I
”.dnim t’now yeht ,edis ruo no si kcul fI“
.deipucco lla era
.stnatibahni reh etipsed lufituaeb si aitamlaD tub
,rebmemer I sa ruos sa yltcaxe hguoht ,eniw eht tuB
,senots eht sa dlo sgnidliub hsawemil dna kcirb fo ytic taerg A
.od I fi naht ,sdael eh fi secnahc retteb dnats ew
”.hguone draeh ev’I ,thgirlA“
”.esoppus I …ecneloiv sseL“
”.su neewteb emoc gnihton tel esiwrehto dna
.tekcop tsaerb ym ni sdnal dna ti morf spils gnihtemos ,ti sllornu eh sA
.reilrae morf segassem terces eht fo eno tuo gnihsif ,tekcaj sih fo tnorf eht nwod gnivid erofeb
”.yob ,ssenisub ruoy fo enon s’tahT“
,krow llits si ti tub ,gniht elbon a si tsixe ot thgir s’eno no tsisni dna ylduorp pu dnats oT
.tnaw I lla s’tahT .snoitcirtser ro secnardnih oN
,ylidaets syas tiK ”,diarfa m’I“
.seog esle enoyreve erehw og ot elba eb ot su tnaw I .xof ,melborp a eb ton ot ti tnaw tsuj I ,kooL ...saw I
.od I ekil leef ot uoy tnaw t’ndid I
.eniw sih spis eh sa desserpminu yldediced ,regnarts eht ta pu skool tiK
.yenom hcum ekam neve t’ndid I .ti od ot tnaw t’ndid I
.ytidica eht yojne I“
,ffilc thgils a otno sgnah daor ehT
.tekcop edisni ym ni peek I ottelits eht mih dnah I
”.edisni eht no elbat a evah ll’ew nehT“
...dna ,erehwemos yella krad a dnif dluohs ew ebyaM“
.htiw ti llihc ot revo tfel eci dah remraf ehT
.kcab ruoy no edih taht peek ot ecnahc eno evah uoy dna ,ffo yad ym s’tI“
,krow ym si scitilop yM
.su sees eh nehw setatiseh neht
”.krow ll’ti ,uoy esimorp I
.em htiw ti gnidneps er’uoy dna
...os dnuos em sekam eh ,ti syas eh yaw ehT
.ris ,uoy dnoyeb ees nac I taht“
.sffuh eh ”,xof ,no maerD“
”?I t’nod ,uoy ezingocer I“ “-
.klaw ew elihw nwod dna pu em gnikool ,sksa eh
,gnola elggig I elihw
gnihtemos s’erehT“
”.deneppah gnihtoN .enif saw gnihtyrevE
.mih llet I ”,gnihton ,hO“
;cilbup eht fo tnavres ro oreh a gnieb rof ton dna ,thgis no em ezingocer ereh elpoep tsoM
.yadot tegrof lliw I
,ecalp taht edisni em tel
”.sevlesruo yojne ot su tnaw tsuj I
,gnikcal meht dnuof dna ,seniw sih deirt ev’I
I .annon detnias ym no raews ,elpicnirp no ti htiw eergasid I dna ,ytilauq roop saw tI
yb kcurts gnieb diova ot
”.ssem siht ni elor ruoy tuoba tegrof ew taht hcum os knird neve thgim eW
.eeffoc fo llems eht ni gniward
,elims enot-gnitlusni-ruoy-raeh-ot-ton-gnidneterp gnitacalp sih selims tiK
.gniwollof fo elbapac ylthgils neve ton m’I hcihw
.ti htiw doom roop ym fo emos yawa gnikat ,nwod em slooc
,tiK ot revo sehcaer wap tfel ym nehT
.em fo dloh a teg ot yrt thgim elpoep ,won thgir no gniog gniht gib a
.gnitsuahxe eb nac tI
.mih llet I ”,ocaC ,yad ykcul ruoy si yadoT“
ssendloc eht ,ssalg eht fo ssendloc eht leef I
.nialpmoc uoy fi dnim t’nod I“ ”?ti si tahW“
.denepmad ylbaredisnoc doom
.ti ni enoyreve etah yeht elihw
.esnopser ni stuop eH
,sih ta tniop neht ,sregnif owt htiw seye ym ta tniop I
.yad s’nam ym ekam ot teg uoy dna
.elims gninniw a gnilims ,mih llet I ”.emaS“
”?gnihtemos wonk ot tnaW“
.ecnartne eht ot revo daeh ew sa ,em serussaer eh
.snedrub lla ni yllauqe erahs ew ,selpuoc rehto ekil ton er’eW .dnim t’nod I
.stop tnalp ro hsart tuo nworht ”yllatnedicca“
”.uoy ot seyb doog yreV“
,gnihtyna deciton ton ev’I fi sa ,rae tfel ym kcilf I
”,esoht tfel I erehw s’taht ,hO“
,htaehs efink eht dna
,ylwols yllufniap ,mih ksa I
,no ti tup nac I erofeb tleb ym sehctans eH
.sredluohs eht yb em sekat dna ,em ot snrut ,shgis eH
,doom ym niur tsuj t’ndid tahT ...tahT“
”?ksa I thgim ,meht no noitavreser a decalp sah ohW“
,tra dna ecneics dna yrtsudni dna
.der worg srae sih sa dnuora gnikool ,selbmum eh
.krims a htiw ,sdon eH
.sresuort ym otni ti gnikcut ,trihs ym pu gninottub ,elbmurg I
.tser fo stnemom deen lla ew ,su no ti ecrof su evol ohw esoht fi nevE
.drager taht ni ,edis ruo no ylerar si kcuL
.ytniatrecnu fo enot a ni syas eh
:na no spahrep ro
,sreggad ekil em gniwollof seye s’tiK htiW
.ylredle era yeht nehw semit dlo doog eht eb lliw yadot fo ssergorp eht
”,won emit gnol a rof siht gninnalp neeb ev’I“
,taht ekil uoy taert meht hctaw dna kcab tis
”?elbat ruo ot teg ew nehw od uoy lliw tahW ?neht dnA“
.od I sa emoclew sa leef nac uoy erehw ,og ot su rof secalp retteb dnif ll’I
.elzzum sih no ecnayonna fo noisserpxe na ,stekcop sih ni swap sih kcits tiK ees I ,seye ym fo renroc eht morF
.ylidaets mih ksa I
.ssik ym htiw mih tpurretni I “-I ,hO“
”.erom rof geb syawla uoy tub-“ “-t’noD“
.liat ym morf gaw ydaets a gniward
ton er’uoy em lleT“
,dworc a hguorht gnissaP
,noitacav a spahrep
,mih dnatsrednu ohw elpoep htiw
.eye ym fo renroc eht morf llet nac I
.em rof gnitadommocca erom dlrow eht gnikam sdrawot ytilibisnopser a sleef eh dnatsrednu I
”.pu-teg siht lla ekil t’nod yllaer I“
,srevoc tsuj ylno tavarc ym hcihw kcen ym dnuora gninnur racs knip a
.niaga stnuah tnasaelpnu hcus tisiv t’nod ew erus ekam dna ,emoh og ,yad a ti llac tsuj dluoc I
.oot ,pu emac eman ruoY
.enola em dna ,em rof devreser era teg I skool wef ehT
.elkcub tleb sih tsniaga gnihsurb
.rood eht ta neht dna
?onilletloC layor a yned erad dluow ohW
”.nialpxe ,xof no oG .edoC“
.nosiop fo slaiv ym
.xof ,eurt s’tahT“ .selggig tiK
.hsurb sreksihw ruO
.ecaep ni tfel er’ew
”?thgirla ,taht ekil dnuos sdrow ym ekam t’nod esaelP
...erom rof ydaer t’nera suolupop ehT“ .selbmum tiK
...tsuj ot gniog ton er’yehT“
.nworf sih si tnavres lanosrep detsurt s’ecarG siH ni esaerc ylno ehT
”.uoy rof ti niur srehto tel t’nod
uoy fI .sretcarahc eseht fo sevil eht gnilcinorhc sgnitniap ruof tsael ta dna slevon lareves no gnikrow yltnerruc s’eH
.thgil yrev os dna niht s’eH
.retteb eht rof dlrow eht gnignahc t’nsi
.gnitnuoc dna sraey ruof
tsitra dna rohtua nA
,raey tsal ekiL“ .syas tiK
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,elbat eht fo egde eht tsap nwod pils wap a tel dna mih ot revo nael I
.shgis neht ,repap eht sllornu eH
”?si boj ym kniht uoy od tahW
,elttob sih revo hctaw I elihW
.tnemeerga elttil ruo srebmemer eh erus sekam ocaC ot ssorca ecnalg A
.gnidnats fo nameltneg enif siht ssik ot gnirad xof redneterp ehT
,ot wap thgir ym no sdnab dlog latnemanro owt dna
,uoy rof ffo tes ev’I emit eht dneps ot tnaw t’nod I
.edistuo sehcneb no ,sanrevat ta tis ro
”.niaga ,emufrep ruoy nettogrof evah ...uoY“ .syas tiK ”,nareiK“
;yrasrevinna ruo s’tI
,ruf dehsaw ,dehsurb naelc htiw xof kcalb A
”?ti saw ,drah os t’nsaw tahT .nareiK ,og uoy erehT“
,enim fo lesaew raed eht ,traeh gnideelb a sah eH
.mih ot ssorca kool dna ,pu nethgiarts I
.nuf yltnatsnoc osla tub ,erus ,ytteP
”,ni uoy wolla t’ndluow yeht taht si riafnu s’tahW“
.spih sih no swap sih stup tiK
.doom evitaklat a ni neeb s’eh dna ,tserra rednu decalp neeb sah otiV dlo raeD“
.flesruoy gniyojne erew uoy esuaceb ,uoy llet ot tnaw t’ndid I ?rebmemer
,did I retfa devirra uoY“
?mh ,su fo eno ylnO“
”,duol os toN“ ”.rellik a sa tub
.syas eh ”,em ot si tI“
”.esaelp ,owt rof elbat a evah ll’eW“
.erom meht yonna ylno ll’tahT
,ytic eht otni taom eltsac dlo eht ssorc ew sA
”.enim tub tnavres s’ydobon er’uoy
.ton ro ot stnaw eh rehtehw ,yaw ym kool ot sah eh taht os ,elzzum sih fo edis tfel eht no sreksihw eht lla psarg I ,wap tfel ym htiW
.hteet sih tuo gnittips enod saw eh ecno
!flesruoy evaheb“ ,mra ym ta sgut eh ”,nareiK“
.nwod srae sih htiw srumrum tiK
,tnaw uoy gnihtyna evah nac uoy dna ,gnir taht hsalF
.nareiK ,serats eht erongI“
,erom daer ot tnaw
.t’ndluoc uoy fi ereh ni su teg dluohs I em dlot uoY .no emoC
”,gnivom teg tsuj s’teL“ ”?yakO“ ”.yakO“
”.elpuoc a ekil ereh steerts eht klaw ot dewolla er’ew taht yppah eb tsuJ“
.sniats doolb dna trid rof meht gnitcepsni dna staps gnidneffo eht tuo gnikahs ,daelp I ”,tiK tuB“
”,uoy ti pots ,hO“  ”.traeh ym skaerb
.od I naht regnorts llems su dnuora elpoep tsom tub
,ratrom dna enots htiw pu tliub
,eruS .tiK ,riaf s’taht kniht t’nod I“
tiaw ot evah lliw I snoitareneg ynam woh rednow em sekam tI
.senil emas eht gnola syob fo sgnitniap dna
”.devreser lla era yehT“
,yawa ti segdun eh tub
,ereh tegrat a teem ot tcepxe t’ndid I
”.tiK ,oot uoy evol I“
niatnuof eutats ylevol a erehw smaerD fo azalP eht otno su stime hcihw
,nwot fo trap siht ni sesuoh recin eht tuoba snoitavresbo gnikam yb gnola mih pleh I tub
”,daeh ruoy ot thgiarts og yeht sa ,seniw ruos ynam os yub ot ton ot esimorp ll’I ,nehT“
,tespu kool t’nseod tiK
”?uoy t’nod ,eman taht wonk uoY“
.rehtegot em dna uoy tsuJ
.em naht ylbatrofmoc erom sehtolc sih sraew tiK
”.tog I skool eht ees t’ndid uoy ,neht neve dna
,enot laivoj a ta gniyrt s’eH
”?ksa ot hcum oot taht si ,yad a rof flesym rof uoy tnaw tsuj I“
.ylreporp tavarc ym eit ot ni gninael ,seunitnoc eh ”,nareiK ,emoC“
,em otni pmub enoemos leef I
.od uoy ekil em ksa uoy nehw on yas t’nac I
”.nekat lla era edistuo selbat ehT“
”.sseug I ,mih truh t’ndid uoy tsael tA“
,elpoep eht fo esuaceb tisiv ot ecin era secalp rehtO
”yrasrevinnA“ saw sihT
”.esimorpmoc a toN
”,edisni elbat a dnif ll’eW“
”?uoy denoitnem neve eh ebyaM
,drows eht rof pooh eht sevomer
”,kaeps em tel lliw eh fi nevE“ ”.wonk uoY“
”.ecin adnik ton s’taht em llet t’nod
”.ekil uoy seniw tahw wonk I“ .selggig tiK
”,kniht uoy naht eroM“
.ti terger t’nod I ,aedi doog a saw ereh gnimoC“
”.lareves ees I dnA
,pu kaeps ot stnaw eh ekil smees tiK
,nerdlihc rieht ot tub ,tsiser lliw elpoep dlO
”.eeffoc uoy evres lliw I ...I“ ”.od ot evah uoy tnatropmi yrev
,oirutneC aiV eht nwod daeh dna ,renroc a dnuor eW
,deecorp ew erofeb ,rehtob eht rof snioc fo elpuoc a droldnal eht syap dna sessalg eht snruter tiK
.em dlot ecno tiK ,ssergorp fo erutan eht si sihT
.si ti looc woh leef dnA
.ynoclab a ekil erom sleef ti stniop ta dna
”.tsrif uoy htiw deraelc ti gnivah erofeb ecalp yna uoy ekat t’now I“
?uoy ot ecneloiv saw tahT ?tahW“
.em yb enif lla s’ti os
,tekcop tsaerb ym fo tuo eton eht llup I ,sregnif owt htiW
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daeR
,raews I“ .sksa erah eht
.emit ecin a gnivah htob su rebmemer I“
”.ytsejaM siH htiw ecneidua na tseuqer ll’I esimorp I dnA
”.gninil revlis a fo hcum ton s’tahT“
”?thgir ,suoires gnieb t’nerew uoY .gniniar saw tI“
,tekcop sih morf reppoc a sekat tiK
,evah rehtar d’I ...seniw
.elihw a retfa ,syas eh ”?nareiK“
.sleef ti woh wonk t’nseod tsuj eh tub
.sessalg eniw fo riap a sworrob dna tnemhsilbatse tseraen eht fo droldnal eht ot revo snur eh
,edisni kcab elffins a sward eh dna ,pu mih skcarc tahT
”.swap gnidloh rof tsuj kcen ruo dnuora esoon a tup d’yeht
”.ocaC ,thgir s’tahT“ ”?eno dnif-F“
”.esirprus yrasrevinna na uoy evig ll’I ebyam
.ereh evres yeht steews dekab eht fo emos yrt dna
.hgis a htiw puc ym hctulc I
.secalp ot ssecca em tnarg yllacigam
.pis elttil a evah ...tsuj thgim I“
.steerts delbboc worran s’aitamlaD hguorht rednaw ew ekil tsuj
.repap pu dellor ,llams a tuo sllup dna tekcop tekcaj ym ni wap sih skcits eH
.gnipoord srae sih htiw syas tiK
.em ot snruter ezag siH
,yrasrevinna ruo s’tI .seY“ ”?od I ...I“ ”.yad
,ainalletsaC ni ,nrob saw I erehw ,wonk uoY“
.sngis ”sexof on“ eht
.erehpsomta sti otni knis ew nehw koon elttil tnasaelp a otni snrut tsaE eht fo esneS ehT
.regnuorcs tseilsaem eht ot nwod ssarb pot eht morF
.gas sredluohs siH
.ecneitap ym gniyrt s’ti dna ,snoitseuq tluciffid ynam os em ksa uoY
”.thgin eht fo erutaerc uoy ,thgilnus emos teg ot dnats dluoc uoy ,sulP“
.yznerf a ni sdon erah ehT
”.ti egnahc ot tnaw I dna
.sliatne taht tahw sdnatsrednu eh erus ekam ll’I neht
.ffo yad a evah ot ekil d’I neht
”.dloheb ot thgis a tahW“ .syas eh
.em morf edih tonnac tiK
.resserd derahs ruo ni sloot eht sdracsid eh sa ,elbmum I
.si ti tahw wonk neve t’nod I .otiV htiw ssenisub taht ni trap on dah I raews I“
.erom pu gnithgil ,syas tiK
.rehtie yppah ton ylraelc s’eh tub
”.tiK ,uoy htiw tsenoh eb ll’I
.seye sih otni thgir gnirats ,drawrof dekrep rae doog ym ,erah eht ot nrut I
...ot tnaw tsuj I ,semitemoS
”?tcepxe uoy did tahW
detnaw ton m’I secalp gnieb em taht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ot evah yllaer I
.nwot fo edis htron eht hcaorppa ew dna no sraew yad eht sa retteb steg tI
.elbmum I ”,ton yltnerappA“
,seiromem esoht lla fo snoitcellocer hguorht srednaw dnim yM
,dloh ot wap ym rof si enigami tsrif I hcihw ,wap a tuo skcits eH
,keehc ym sekorts eH
.snrettap etihw dna nworb hserf-gnirps sih setautnecca hcihw tavarc knip elap ,tfos a dna
,nihtiw diuqil eht fo
.pihsdrah etipsed lufsseccus dna hcir
,nelarD yb uoy rof daer ,ffutsyttopS yb
.elttob eht gnikroc dna ssalg sih gninwod ,syas eh
”.tespu erew uoy em llet t’ndid uoY
.seton wef a tsuj s’ti ,tiK ,kooL“
.feiler emoclew a si ,sgnidliub yb detcurtsbonu ,ezeerb looc eht
.kcen ym dnuora ti parw dna elbat edisdeb ym morf tavarc ym ekat I
,yadoT“ .syas tiK
.seye sih sllor tiK ”.ekil I revenehw
.dnalemoh sih morf senut klof emos pu staeb ohw ,reyalp elddif gnillevart a semoc gnineve eht htiW
,gnitisiv peek ylbaborp ll’I eno si ecalp siht esuaceB
.tekcop tsaerb edisni sih ni eton repap eht skcits eH
?rebmemer ,sseldrager ni em tel ll’yehT“ .repsihw I ”?oS“
,eeffoc lufthgiled su evres ot teg uoY
,yletaidemmi sdnopser ohw ,ocaC ot revo ecnalg a worht I .elballortnocnu
”,uoy rehtob ti tel ot ton yrt tub ,wonk I“
,daor eht fo edis eht gnola srodnev htiw edart ,nwod dna pu llim elpoep ,ereH
;eunevA elivreS ot teg ot deen I“
.yawa teg ot seganam eh erofeb ralloc s’erah eht barg I ,noitom kciuq a htiW
.taht ekil t’nod yeht ;xof a er’uoY
,”tsaE eht fo esneS ehT“ ,esuoh eeffoc ehT
.stekcop tekcaj ym fo eno ot snoitisnart thgiew a dna
”.reisae ti evah su retfa emoc ohw esoht
,puc sih otni yldexif serats eh esuaceb
,yrassecen yltcirts s’ti nehw ylno em htiw krow ym ekat ot esimorp I ,nruter nI“
.seye neerg gib sih htiw em ta gnizag
.tiK ta ecnalg neht ,mih ta don I
”.og ot tnaw I dnA
htiw eussi ekat I“
.worromot rebmemer thgim I
.elttob a sekat dna ,snioc wef a mih sevig tiK tub
.hgih tuons sih sesiar eH
”,em ot tespu mees t’ndid uoY“
”,oneneV otiV fo dneirf yreve ezingocer I“ .sksa erah ehT
”?ereht tog ev’uoy ngis taht rof tnuocsid a gnitteg eb ew lliW“
”?uoy t’ndid ,hcum sa dias uoY
.nem neewteb nevE
taht dnatsrednu ot uoy deen I tuB
”,tniop a tog ev’uoy ,thgirlA“
daor eht fo elddim eht ot peek I yhw ro ,swodniw yrots dnoces ni sannon dlo morf teg I serats gnol noitnem t’nod I
,yppah em ekam ot tnaw uoy fI ?wonk uoy
,su ekil elpoep ot tfig a si ecalp sihT
,od uoy lliw tahw dnA“
,lareneg ni ,snezitic naitamlaD gniht doog a s’tI
,elbuort otni meht teg taht selzzum bmud gib dna
”.udrep sius ej …yas uoy woh …em esucxE“
”.yadot hctib a si nus ehT
.htaeneb yab naitamlaD eht fo weiv eht yojne ot pots I ,gniliar a tA
s’erehT .boj sih gniod tsuj
.cigam yb neppah t’now taht tub ,yad eno ,thgim yehT
”!edisyrtnuoc eht ni cincip a detnaw I“
.htaehs sih dna ,stsirw ytniad sih ,kcen rednels sih nO
”?thgir ,gnihton naht retteB
.dnim rieht egnahc ot xof eht ton m’I tuB“ .pil ym etib I
.tniop I erehw gnikool neve ton ,em ta gniwob ,syas eh ”,knahT“
.niaga seye ym otni kool ot mih ecrof I erofeb
.nwod rae doog ym nrut I
,wenk eh eman yreve tuo taps eH
.dednah yvaeh os eb ot evah t’nod uoy tuB“
.nur ot stnaw eh ekil skool eh dna ,mih fo og tel I
,gnir ym ot kcab dna ,tiK ot ,em morf gnitrad seye sih ,sdon erah ehT
.emoserit s’ti dna ,gninrom lla gninialpmoc neeb ev’uoY“ .selbmurg eh
.won em rof krow si sihT“
...t’ndid I ...yrros m’I“
”?uoy tuoba tegrof d’ew kniht uoy diD
,ylduol ffins I ”...dnif I“ “-
.em ta gnirats elihw ti stekcop eH
”?oot worromot tegrof I rehtar uoy dluoW
…ebyam ,ti tuoba swonk eh fI“
.seye ym ot kcab neht dna
.yltnetsisni erah eht ta skool dna
”.ruos oot s’tI ?uoy od ,yadot taht knird ot naem uoy esoppus t’nod I“
,tsiaw ym dnuora snottub eht netsaf dna ,taoc kcalb ym otni gurhs I
.elttil a pu nethgil em spleh ekoj eht tub
”?nam ym htiw eussi ekat uoy oD“
”.doom eht niur ot tnaw t’ndid I“
”?mmh ,em rof elims a no tup ,xof ,no oG
,si taht nehw wonk uoy tel ll’I
.rof gnikool s’eh sdrow eht gnidnif ta tpmetta deliaf erar a ni ,shgis eH
.ynapmoc tneced sah xof drawyaw eht taht enoyreve wohs ot fi sa resolc em sgut dna
tsuj ot drah os s’tI .uoy htiw gnorw
.dlrow eht egnahc ot gniyrt
.spil sih kcep dna ecnatsid eht esolc I
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.seveels trihs ym otni meht gninottub dna ,ksed a morf sknilffuc ym gnikat ,yas I ”,naem I“
.yawa og regnarts eht ekam ot repap eht no ecalp modnar emos no tniop I
,kcab rewol s’tiK ot nwod edils wap ym tel I
.eunitnoc I ”,wonk uoy tuB“
.redluohs ym no daeh sih gninael
.daeh eht no lian eht tih tsuj ev’I snaem hcihw
.enim htiw tuons sih elzzun ot revo nael I
”!tsenif eht-ht ylnO-O-
,seitud ruoy morf ffo yad a rof uoy devorppa ev’I“ .syas eh
”.spil ruoy no eniw tog ev’uoY“ .elims I
”,ynnuf t’nsi sihT“
.t’now I .nareiK ,em tsurt ,hO“
,god.ecioveht ta
,thguob eh elttob eniw eht ytpme I dna tiK
.meht hsinif dna ,hgual
.sehtolc yadnuS elbatrofmocnu yletarepsed ym fo taeh eht dna
,ruoivaheb tseb ruoy no er’uoy fi dnA“ .syas eh
,setihw sih sa ruos sa noisserpxe na htiw mar ylloow a
.rehtegot tneps ev’ew stnemom fo seiromem eht lla htiw em setallitit emufrep detnecs-esor thgil siH
. semitemos ffo elpoep eseht tes ot hguone si ecnalg a nevE
,ti revocsid ot tiK swolla tnecs dlim esiwrehto yM
:tnemeerga nekopsnu na s’tI
.noisacco laiceps eht etiuq
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ti gnivah m’I sa gnol os evah I tahw erac t’nod I ,hturt ni nehw
.teerts peets a otno ,sesacriats emos pu bmilc trohs a s’ti ,ereht morF
”?thgirla ,doom eht deniur uoY“
.rae sih ni repsihw I ”,spoO“ “-
.htaerb fo trohs su gnivael neve ,troffe na s’tI
.gniwollaws dna gnitatiseh ,yas I
”.deedni yad enif A“ .selims eh
”,rood taht hguorht deppets uoY“
taht os ,meht rof degnahc sdnim rieht deen yehT
.rood eht sediseb pu sngis denmad esoht fo eno tog s’ti dnA
”?tniop eht ot teg
.etalocohc ym gnippis
.egassem a tsuj s’tI .yrros ,yrroS“ ”!nareiK“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”,uoy fo lla ...llems nac I“
”?eson ym pu deppots wohemos thguob uoy eniw ruos taht kniht uoY
,accoB aiV gnidniw ,worran eht otno nrut ew ,oirutneC aiV morF
,od I esuaceb tsuj ffo syad ekat meht ekam t’nac I
”.ereh dnuora thgir eb dluohs ti ,og s’teL
,trihs etihw krats a
”?owt rof elbat a tuoba uoy sksa eh nehw
,boj ym morf skaerb tneuqerf erom gnikat tuoba kniht ot esimorp ll’I dnA“
”,won su erutpac dluoc taht retniap a dah ew hsiW“
.gnipoord sreksihw dna srae sih htiw ,demahsa ylhguoroht skool ydaerla eh tuB
…t’nseod ohw elpoep ot sneppah tahw
”?owt rof elbat-t A ...A“
,ereh era steerts eht naelc woh dna
ffutsyttopS yb ”yrasrevinnA“
,yaw gnorw eht ti tuoba gniog s’eh taht mih llet nac I
ot yltcerid nekops reven ev’I
.emit gnol a rof toN
.seye sih gnipiw ,syas eh
”?ti hsinif ot gniog uoy erA“
.won syad wef tsal eht rof setaicossa sih pu gnirehtag dnuora gniog neeb ev’eW
,noissucsid lacitilop a ni su egagne revo elbat eht morf dneirf tac naisreP sih dna noiL A
,ffutsyttopS yb ”yrasrevinnA“
”,detpecca ygolopA“
.og eno ni ti snwod dna spil sih ot ti stup tiK “-I“
,rettuc yvan a no tnew ew tuB“ .dias I
,ereh erom yaws seert ehT
”.raed ym ,uoy retfA“
.yllanoisacco noops llams a htiw ti ni gnirrits
.smra sih sdlof erah ehT
.em ot revo ti gninrut erofeb
”.evarg ruo ot yaw ruo no yojne nac ew stifeneb emos htiw semoc krow ym tsael tA“
.flesruoy rof em tnaw uoy nehw detcirtser os leef ot evah t’nod uoy taht os
.sksa tiK ”?ecnirp ehT“
”.ti knird t’nod ,neht lleW“
”?uoy ksa eh did tahW“
.won elbat nwo ruo evah eW“
”.yaw eht ni teg t’now tI .syawyna ,yas ot tog ev’yeht tahw wonk ydaerla I
.lliw yeht esruoc fO“ ”?taht esilaer uoy
”?ew llahs ,etsat a evah s’teL“
”?won tsuj uoy ot kaeps devoleb ym raeh ton uoy diD“ “-nees t’nevah I
.fo sevorppa tiK gnihtemos gniod m’I taht spleh osla tI
”.od uoy seY“ ”?wonk t’nod ...I“
.em ot esolc mih gnidloh
.egap yrruFoS sih tuo kcehc
.gnihgual dna redluohs ym ta gnippals ,syas tiK
,mih ksa I ”?ti si tahW“
.xedni ym htiw pu elzzum sih gnitfil
”.rehtie ,taht ton s’ti wonk uoY“
,yb sessap seye esnetni dna stops kcalb dna nworb htiw tac egnarts A
.ylhtooms seog tser ehT
...doom gnisimorp eht ni er’ew ecniS“
,resolc snael dna enim otni mra sih skooh eh
.yadot rof nwod krow ym lla tup ot dediced ev’I dna
.elims yfoog a stoohs eH
,wap tfel ym no tengis a peek I ,gnir ybur eht htiw gnolA
.seiretra niam s’ytic eht fo eno si hcihw
”.tiK ,oot taht tnaw I“
sseccus s’eripmE eht no gnitsaoc
.krab I ”,ereht ,ti dloH“
”.gnissarrabme s’tI
,gnissim rae na fo flah
.ocaC ,ocaC ,ocaC .ocaC“ ”?lliw uoY“
.renwo eht no rebmun a od yllaer ot dah I
straeh gib htiw syob fo seirots no gnisucof