,seye rebma dna ruf nworb krad fo tlep a dah ehS
.deton liatkraD ronrevoG
,steppup rehto eht fo eno
noihsuc dezis nagazaw a no deggel-ssorc tas hadhaF
.derewsna tseirp eht
.dnuorg eht no taps dna seye reh depiw hadhaF "?'riafnU'"
.yawllah eht fo dne eht ta srood elbuod dezalg fo riap a ot meht del ehS
,reciffo noitcetorP liviC a ot kaeps ot reh rof redro na eriuqer tsuj dluow taht yleruS
"?steppup sti fo eno emoceb ot
hadhaF tnemom a rof taht railimaf os dna peed
,nomed eht rof saloR droL derutpac eW"
"?noitpmeder dnoyeb era uoy emussa uoy dluow yhW" .deilper eh
,ni dehtaerb hadhaF .deilper ehs
?ereh uoy era yhW"
,pmoc mlap sih no nottub a dehcuot namerof eht sa ,edutitarg ni daeh reh dekcud ehs woN
"?od uoy did tahw oS"   ".dias ehs sa
,srotisiV ehT rellirht if-ics eht fo retirw
.yawa meht nrut naht
".erutnedni fo emitefil a ecaf ot ylno
",noitseuq erom enO"
",ega ym ni modsiw on deniag evah I raef I hguohT
.lleH taht morf esaeler em tnarg ot
",ilA ot dnetxe ton did ytleurc fo ecnatpecca ruoY"
,tseirP retueN a fo sebor etihw derediorbme eht ni desserd nagazaw A
esuba lauxes dna
.ssarG tfoS fo yellaV eht fo ,enotsdnaS nalC fo hadhaF ,sgniteerG"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,yad ecyoR yb
?yaw siht ni deronoh gnieb I ma yhW
.revo si tfihs ruoY"
,nevig saw ehs ecnawolla doof eht htiw thguob
.gnidaelp sselhtrow reh htiw ,os doG tlusni ton dluow ehS
.kcab gnippets dna etulas ni daeherof sih ot sregnif owt gnihcuot
.emarF niaP eht no reh gnuh dna
.gnikahs reh gnivael
.ecaps sdlroW deillA deklats taht setarip live tsom eht fo eno ot devalsne
.gnireffus erom on
".enod evah I tahw ,fo detcivnoc saw I tahw wonk tsum uoY
,liatkraD arevillaS ydaL fo
.efil ym ni niap elbirret tsom eht tlef I neht dna ,kcab dekan ym pu nur elcatnet s'nomed eht tlef I"
",pordsevae ot sa edur gnieb rof ezigolopa I"
.taK-ilA elttil fo dnof neeb dah I taht gniwonk
robal drah fo emitefil a ,raelc si ecnetnes yM" .dnim reh morf sbewboc yraew raelc ot deirt ehs sa daeh reh gnikahs ,mih deksa hadhaF "?naem uoy od tahW"
ruryahk atna'aw mahraw rifhgibbar ruqaW   .rewop gnivah fO
.ecno dnab live taht ni etarip a neeb dah ehs wenk ereh enoyreve tub
,ratla eht morf mih esaeler dluoc ew erofeb tuB
.dnilb naht erom erew seye yM"
.devirra d'ehs nehw noisufnoc reh ni ylsuoiverp deciton t'ndah ehs taht
.reh gniruces erew srehto eht elihw ,kcen s'radanilA dnuora dnah ym tup dna pu dehcaer I oS .ylkciuq tca ot dah I wenk I"
,derutpac saw radanilA retfA"
.llew sa tas yeht sa
,ezorf nagazaw llat ehT    .yletaidemmi
!sredle ym naht retteb wenk I thguoht ohw htuoy tnagorra na saw I
.ylfeirb hteet reh neewteb pil reh deirrow ehS .dias hadhaF ",hO"
.erew teef dekan reh ytrid woh fo erawa yllufniap nagazaw eht gnikam
.snehctik s'ronrevoG eht morf ,doof laeR ".snehctik
.yltneg deksa ladiN namI
.erofeb sraey net ,dnuof d'ew esab gnileufer a no diar dehctob
,oga emit gnol a ,ecno ohW
,reh hguorht nur redduhs a tlef hadhaF ".taK-
.thgir os sehsid eht ekam ot
noicipsus ni reh ta pu dekool rood eht ta draug ehT
,dnammoc eht si miH roF
.ti detset ti os ,enim sa gnorts sa ydob
"'.reh revo dloh on evah lliw ograM
.snis ym rof ,em rof dednetni dah doG tnemhsinup eht yllanif saw siht gnikniht ,dam tnew I nehT
.enihs dna netsilg
,taK-ilA tsuj neeb dah
. yaD ecyoR yb serutnevdA nexiV deR ehT dna
,eman rieht si yloh
stnemecalper evren laicifitra dna yregrus etaciled fo shtnom xiS
,em rof yllaicepse edam saw sihT
",hadhaF ,yadot krow dooG
.deerga radanilA ",eurT"
,sserd eulb tnagele na gniraew
.ssarG tfoS fo yellaV eht ni
,ecaf derracs a htiw nexiv eraps ,niht a saw meht rof gnitiaw ereht gnittis dnA
.emusnoc ot ti rof yab eht otni …ti fo tsom …deef
".tliub dah ograM ydaL ecived erutrot a s'tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
",tsael ta ,ecno naht erom dias nami ym gnihtemos saw tI
.etarip rehtona fo ecivres eht ni ,werc reh fo ruof dellik dah lrig ehT
,liatkraD arevillaS
,derewsna neht dna
.tespu gnikool ,dias radanilA
,lotipac eht fo retnec eht ta gnidliub kcirb yrots eerht a
.ylpmis derewsna radanilA
"?uoy koot nailadra eht nehw ,deneppah tahW"
.deirc ehs "!doG luficreM"
",dlrow siht no semirc on dettimmoc uoy sa ,revewoH"
.lleH fo sraey owt retfa
"?yllacificeps ,sredro hcihW"
".snoitca rieht ot eye dnilb a nrut ot gnilliw tsael ta erew uoy tub ,setarip wollef ruoy fo emos sa leurc sa ton erew uoy spahreP"
.ti esufer dna uoy tlusni ton lliw I
,telkna gnirotinom reh evomer ot detpmetta ton dah ehs erus ekam ot
,tnemtrapa elttil depmarc eht ot kcab thgiarts klaw ot retteb ti dnuof ehs ecitcarp nI
.ksa ton derad ehS
",hallamsiB"   ".yrros m'I"
,llew sa detpmet eb thgim dna ,taK-ilA nwonk dah taht werc reh ni srehto yna taht os
.kinatlus meeza'aw akihjaw ilalajil ihgabnay amak udmah lakal ibbar aY    .enon devresed ehs wenk ehs nehw
hguohT" .deerga hadhaF ",seY"
.decniw radanilA hguoht
,evresed ton did ehs wenk ehs selcarim lacideM
,retaw eht otni tuo taob rieht hsup su dah nomed ehT
,sseniraew ni niaga nwod pmuls sredluohs reh gnileef
.liatkraD ronrevoG ot wal-ni-retsis ,einaleM ydaL yb deerf gnieb erofeb
;tnemhsinup reh tuo evres ylreporp dluoc ehs os
,yas ot nageb hadhaF ",…esuaceB"
,tnemom a rof siht redisnoc ot demees liatkraD ronrevoG
".sredro s'ogra'aM ydaL yebosid ot detpmetta I
,denepo
,niaga dam gniog ylerus saw ehs thguoht
.nialpxe ll'ehS"   .deggeb ehs "?yhW"
.dlihc deracs ,llams a saw ehs esuaceB
",os reffus radanilA ees naht
.tsehc reh ni thgil os tlef hturt krad siht yhw derednow dna ,deilper hadaF
.demrifnoc radanilA
.resolc pets ot gnirad ton
.ronrevog yratenalp s'emlohneerG
!devalsnE" .deirc hadhaF "!dlihc a
.ylsuoituac deksa hadhaF "?seY"
.semirc reh rof esnepmocer elap ni
,swalc eot s'hadhaF rednu dekcilc dna ,elbram etihw evitan fo edam erew sroolf ehT
.enod dah I taht live eht lla tegrof em depleh ti
,yaD ecyoR yb ”reyarP tA“
".drawretfa ,em ot deneppah dah derednow evah dluow uoy esle
,niaga klaw ot elba eb neve dluow ehs rehtehw elbanoitseuq neeb dah ti emit a roF ".nac
?yhW .dezilaer ehs
,radanilA gnipleh
erutnedni ruoy eunitnoc ot
,stimil erew ereht tub
,em llik ot doG deggeb I dnim ym ni
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,gnineve-dim litnu won morf eerf saw emit reh yroeht nI
.rennuts a htiw em tohs ograM
)".ycrem wohs ohw esoht fo
.dias ladiN namI
nepo slirtson reh tlef ehS
.dnalsI s'nomeD eht no ratla eht ot dnuob dna
.daeh reh koohs neht ,dias ehs
,tnemom a rof ti ta derats ehS
.deksa nexiv elttil eht
.liatynop sti ni htrof dna kcab gniylf riah eulb dekaerts yerg reh
elkna s'hadhaF dnuora dekcol telkna gnirotinom eht gnittel
.ereh saw ehs yhw gnirednow llits ,dewollof hadaF dna
",hcum t'nsaw hcihw ,dluoc I tahw did I"
evigrof ot dettimrep ton era yeht doG
.setamwerc dlo reh fo eno fo lairt a ni desu eb ot noitamrofni gnikees saw liatkraD ronrevoG fi derednow ehS
",enotsdnaS nalC fo hadhaF ,nosrep tnasaelp yrev a ton erew uoy taht
?nalc suoethgir a fo rethguad demahs eht morf raeh ot tnaw yeht dluow yhW"
".drah gnikrow neeb ev'uoy syas namerof ruoY ?yadot yad dooG"
",ilA ot gnikaeps neeb ev'I"
.tnemesuma s'nomed eht rof ...sgniht ...od ot edaM
.gnisselb devresednu rehtonA
.emoh morf setsat railimaf eht ta
.emirP agazaW fo noiger treseD eulB eht morf aet fo ylppus decirp ylraed dna llams yrev a htiw gnola
"?htaed elbaborp ruoy denruom ylpeed os dah yeht nehw
".ecivres s'ograM ydoolB ni tneps htob uoy emit eht dna ,uoy tuoba gniksa"
,rood tnorf eht dehcaorppa hadhaF sa
,lavivrus ruoy etarbelec ot ecnahc eht meht yned uoy dluow yhW"
.metsys suovren ym ot flesti detcennoc ti elihw
,tsol demees lla nehw ,thguoht ralimis a dah I wonk ot uoy esirprus ti dluoW"
,nailadra eht fo sdnah eht ta tnemrot ruoy fo noitingocer nI
,efil reh fo emit taht tuoba hcum klat t'nseod ilA"
,dias radanilA
,snroht evren s'nailadra eht yb derutcnup droc lanips reh gnivah fo sraey owt retfa
.reh ta nwod delims ,etihw riah
.reh dlot radanilA
,ytirohtua mlac fo ria na eduxe ot demees ehs taht etipseD
.ronrevog eht ekil dednuow neeb dah ohw eno ot
.tluda na sa dettimmoc erew semirc ruoy ,flesruoy dias uoy sA"
,ecar traeh reh tlef hadhaF
,degdelwonkca draug eht ",ma'aM"
.sisao nedrag ,mlac ,teiuq siht fo yhtrownu dna ytrid dna ybburg gnileef ,niaga daeh reh koohs hadhaF "…tub ,on-
,noihsaf nagazaw eht ni htob ,sdnah reh htiw flesreh devres dna
,efas dna yppah tlef ehs stnemom feirb eht fo skaeps ehs nehw
.gninrom eht ni etis krow eht ot kcab troper ot deriuqer saw ehs litnu ,emoh reh ot nruter tsum ehs nehw
,ylhsifles erom ,dnA
,ton did uoy retteB"
,lortnoc s'nomed nailadra eht fo eerf saw ehs esuaceB
,lanif ylrettu hguoht ,htaed semitemoS
,nageb liatkraD ronrevoG
.nwod meht tnuh ot edam erew ew sa meht gnippart
",evah dluohs yeht llew sA"
.radanilA pleh ot gnihtemos od dluow I wenk ehs em dlot ograM
.senob dna selcsum reh ni nwonk sevlesmeht gnikam robal s'yad eht fo sehca eht lla
.gurhs a htiw dias hadhaF
.hadhaF ot dias liatkraD ronrevoG
,denethgirf ,llams a
,skcolb nietorp detutitsnocer paehC ".emoh
llet nac uoy enigami ot ,eb tsum uoy tnagorra woH .hadhaF raed ,hO" ,ria eht otni gniyas
erew uoY !taK-ilA ,hO"
.reh derutrot ograM
.revo eb lliw ti neht ,kcen reh pans I fI' ,thguoht dna
.moc.nozamA ta
,evila saw ehs esuaceB
).ytngierevos taerg ruoY dna
a ti def reven dah ograM
,ylluferac deiduts evah ot dah fehc s'liatkraD ronrevoG
.ylwols nageb
.snedrag lairomem s'noisnam eht otni tuo denepo srood eht taht gniees ,trohs deppots hadhaF
,renroc eno ni cincip rennid a gnivah saw ylimaf nexof A
.serusaert nettog-lli sti daolffo ot
?ycrem hcus detnarg ehs saw yhW ?ereh ehs si yhW
,nwo reh naht rellams ecar a rof tliub
reh gnileef ,yltfos dias hadhaF ",detauteprep ytleurc si
.secneirepxe rieht ssucsid
.maercs ton dluoc I tpecxE
,dnalsI s'nomeD eht ta devirra nexof owt eht nehT"
.s'radanilA pirg ot revo dehcaer wap s'ronrevog ehT
,redilghgiH hguaniveK droL ,dnabsuh etal yM"
",uoy was neve reven I ,neht dnuora niap hcum os ni saw I"
taht wonk dluohs srenetsil
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.dnatsrednu liatkraD ronrevoG ekam ot woh erus ton ,deppots neht
.evila reh gnidnif yppah ton saw ograM
.tsael ta egatnavda eno saw erehT
"?lla ta gnihtyna od yhW"
laes lanosrep eht deyalpsid saw neercs eht nO
,pu ekops eciov wen A
.lufetarg saw yltsenoh ehs dnA
.eerf saw I tub ,daed ylerus saw ehs wenk dna
.dias ronrevoG eht
".dlrow siht no
.hcamots reh htiw level saw elzzum s'namerof eht elihw ,llat sretem flah a dna owt dionamuh cinocard yleugav a
.ti pots ton dluoc I tub
,erab reh devahs ograM tub ,gniyd
.teppup rehtona otni mih edam ohw
,ees uoy gnitiaw dna gnihctaw neeb dah ehS
.emas eht did sedarmoc ym nehw morf yawa ecaf ym denrut
"?tey netae uoy evaH"
,oga sraey eerht diar lanif s'ograM ydaL ni ynoloc eht dekcatta taht werc eht ni neeb t'ndah ehS .tuo og naht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.yltneg detcerroc radanilA ",srevotfel toN"
,sseltneleR eht draoba emit rieht morf emankcin dlo s'radanilA esu dna
.telkna gnirotinom eht gniton
'.riafnu' fo em ot kaeps ton oD"
nalc ym nopu kcab ym denrut I
,wollahs gniworg gnihtaerb reh
.daeh reh dekcoc liatkraD ronrevoG   .dias hadhaF
reerac reh tuoba snoitseuq rewsna yllanoisacco ot dna
,smitciv ym ot taht lleT
,lairt ruoy fo tpircsnart eht gnidaer morf ,rehtag I"
,gnidnatsrednu dna tnemenota ,lavivrus tuoba si yrots eht elihW :gninraw tnetnoC
".no oG .ycrem a si
,deton ronrevog eht
,edih eulb nwo s'hadaF ot nosirapmoc ni
,dehcterts ecnelis eht sA
.ycarip ni reerac ruoy gnirud ,meht tcatnoc ot hsiw ton thgim uoy yhw dnatsrednu I"
,laeh dna revocer ot ,sraey owt rof derutrot eb oT
.esirprus ni gniknilb ,deksa hadhaF "?ereH"
.efil eritne ym ni ,detaloiv os ,sselpleh os tlef reven dah I
stnalp evitan fo erutxim a htiw nedrag cilbup gnitivni na yb dednuorrus
",hadhaF ,gnineve dooG"
.meht derongi ehS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,daeh reh koohs hadhaF
.deb egairram ruo no em depar
,wolloh eciov reh
,htgnerts nagazaw reh htiw ,hadhaF roF
secaR xiS eht fo rehto ynA
,reh fo edis rehtie ot tlenk
,dedda eh ,dnopser ot deliaf ehs nehW ".ssarG
"?gninetsil uoy erew yhW
",ssoB ,sknahT"   .lleH ni
.denrae dah I tnemhsinup eht roF
.flesreh dettimrep ehs emoh fo rednimer ylno eht saw tI
hadhaF ",radanilA fo dnof neeb dah I taht wenk ograM"
,dehgis ehS   .dias ladiN
,kniht llits dluoc I
.feiler ni debbos ehs sa thgit reh gnidloh
,eugnot nagazaw eht ni deteerg radanilA
.ycrem s'doG fo yhtrow llits saw I kniht dna ,flesym ot eil dluoc I ,reh gnipleh ni esuaceB
".ylraed os evol uoy enoemos tuoba ,taht gnikniht rof ,em etah tsum uoy wonk I"
",werc eht fo tsrow eht morf ,em detcetorp ehS"
.desolc noisserpxe reh
!em dellortnoc regnol on nomed ehT
".ereh ecnanep ym eunitnoc lliw I dna
".msirohpa na ekil sdnuos tahT"
,ssenevigrof degaruocne taht doG a dah nexof tsenoh yltsom dna derutan doog ehT
.noitseuq rehto eht rewsna ot deliaf ehs nehw
meht ekam ot slio lagelli ylbaugra dna laiceps no stiderc dnasuoht a revo tneps ecno d'ehS
,erutnedni reh fo trap sa
saw od em dah ti gniht tsrif ehT
esuaceb ,llew yrev edih ot denrael taht seno eht era yeht tuB
.hcaorppa s'hadhaF ta noisneherppa ni pu gnikool stnerap eht
.deilper hadhaF ",seY"
!ycrem dna ssenevigrof su tnarG !droL ruO"
,radanilA ta ylitliug gnicnalg ,desuap hadhaF   .desserp ehs
.dnim reh ni pu llew ot nageb seiromem suonosiop sa
.deddorp liatkraD ronrevoG
.draeh dah hadhaF os ro
dettimrep ytleurC"
,tuo meht dekculp dah I taht retteB
,sdlrow neila ,egnarts no gniklaw fO
,reh llik dluoc I erofeb tuB
,deksa ehs ",tak-ilA"
.em ot riafnu etiuq smees tI"
".uoy
dewolla saw ehs esuaceB
.reyarp ni ton tub ,ecnelis ni
.rennam nexof eht ni devres t'nsi ti dna
taht ni deid dah ehs taht thguoht lla eW
".noitacifidom ot nepo si ecnetnes ruoy tuo evil uoy erehw" ,dedda ladiN
,yawa dekalf lla t'ndah yeht lufetarg tsuj saw ehs syad esehT
.hadhaF ,won stluda htob era eW"
.sgnirts sti gnillup nomed eht tuohtiw
?nexiV deR eht yb deucser erew ew erofeb tsuj
!ssensuoethgir fo daetsni nis fo htap eht esohc dna
"?lauqe na ekiL"   "…ekil
".em deucser illaS nehw ti ffo gnignah llits saw I"
,evael ruoy ekat yam uoy nehT
".rebmemer I dlihc yrgna eht regnol on era uoY
…ekil uoy ot klat t'nac I ,yrros m'I"
,em dennuts ehs yhw s'tahT
,ruf kcalb hsiyerg fo tlep a htiw ,stsinoloc s'emlohneerG fo ytirojam eht ekil ,nexoF a saw eH
,ralucric a revo esor seerT
.niaga ydob reh fo lortnoc lluf hadhaF nevig dah
,nomed ruoy yb teppup a sa nekat saw saloR rehtorb ym nehW
.semitemos ,yawa teg emoS
,timmoc I did nis fo sraey ytrihT
,kaeps regnol on dluoc I
,ta dekcod sseltneleR eht
,yas oS( .neemihar
”reyarP tA“:yojne esaelP
.deb ograc s'kcurt dnuorg eht otno kcab sloot fo etarc eht detfil ehs sa ,kcab reh no nwod taeb nus noonretfa etal ehT
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll’I
ecneserp suoirolg ruoY ot gnittifeb si hcihw ,uoY ot eud si ecarg llA !droL ym hO(
.dias namerof eht
.won peew dluoc I esuaceb
,pmad dna dloc oot saw ti gnihtyna fI
",hadhaF raed ,enif si 'ladiN'"
.ti dellup hadhaF dna ,tekcaj reh ni dezzub pmoc mlap reH
"?ksir eht ekat yhW
,reh etisoppo tes noihsuc a no nwod tas eH
,ekil demees evah thgim tnemetats tsal taht tlusni eht dezilaer evah dluohs ehs ,etal ooT ".yawa
ladiN namI dna radanilA .pans yllanif
?ereht detnaw eb ehs dluow yhW
.etis krow eht evael ot eerf saw ehs taht wonk
"?ereh ssenisub ruoy s'tahW"
.ilA llik ot deirt uoy fi ,dehsinup eb ot gniog erew uoy wenk uoY"
"?snis ym fo knits eht htiw meht nekcis ot hsiw I dluow yhW
.ydob ym fo lortnoc ni regnol on saw I tub ,niap dna tsriht ,regnuh sa hcus ,snoitasnes leef llits dluoc I
.reh ta kool ot smra reh gnissorc
,niap erom on leef lliw ehS
.tuo dnuof uoy sa ,derutrot ro ,delliK
.evila erew uoy taht dnif ot desirprus etiuq saw I ,noitautis ruoy ssucsid ot dlrow ylevol siht ot em detivni liatkraD ronrevoG nehW"
.nalc ruo fo sredle eht htiw noitcnujnoc ni
,kcab dekool ohw ,liatkraD ronrevoG ta revo dekool ehS
.dlrow siht fo relur etulosba
.ecalaP s'ronrevoG eht ot og ot deksa neeb ecno reven dah ehS
.gniraew neeb dah yeht kaolc refoops eht fo sdlof eht kcab gniward
tseB eht era uoY roF
.lortnoc deniager d'ehs retfa
,emirP agazaW ot refsnart ruoy timrep ot eerga yeht
!gnisselb a ylurT
.draytruoc devap kcirb
uoy rof enod evah yam I sessendnik llams on dna
.eH tub dog on si ereht ,hallA si eH dnA(
,ecitsuJ fo yrtsiniM sdlroW deillA eht ot nekops sah liatkraD ronrevoG"
".ti fo retteb kniht dluow
,niaga ekops neht dna
,dias hadhaF "?tahW"
,gniht doog eno siht did I fi esuaceB
.meht tsap gnol devom dah hadhaF dna
,tsehc reh morf pu tsrub bos gnikcarw ,taerg A
.yletaidemmi noisnaM s'ronrevoG eht ot tropeR
,egassem elpmis eht saw ti woleB
,eid ot derreferp evah dluow I esuaceB"
.serats eht ot desu saw ehS
.ylevitatnet deksa ehs "?ladiN namI"
,gnigru s'ronrevog eht tA
.neeb evah thgim tI .wonk t'nod I"
.esirprus ni niaga deknilb nagazaw ehT
,erutnedni ruoy fo sraey owt tsal eht ni roivaheb erecnis ruoy dna
,regnif a evom ton dluoc I
.ydob nwo ym htiw tliub nosirp a ni deppart dnim ym ,sraey owT
,lairt ym ta segduj eht dlot I sA"
.draug eht dlot ,radanilA ,nexiv eht
,dednuow ydaerla saw ehS
,doG ot reyarp dna gnisselb a em tnarg ot hsiw uoy fI"
,daor eht nwod degdurt hadhaF
.rennid etarobale siht ton
Y"   "?ti t'nsah ,emit gnol yrev a neeb s'tI"
!eciohc on dah uoY
.ylrettib deilper ehs
,ssendlim gnisirprus htiw dias liatkraD ronrevoG
?ereht og ot deen reve ehs dluow yhW
.kcab reh dniheb stnemmoc derettum eht ot eht desU
.emahs dlo ni nrub skeehc dna srae
.nedrag eht otni tuo reh del radanilA ".gnola emoC
.hgual feirb a tuo deffuhc ehS
tsuj ro ,dellik ro truh I mohw seno eht
.dah ti taht teppup tsekaew eht llik
".emoh eb tsael ta nac uoy tub
",neht uoy deef ll'eW"
"?ereh ecnetnes ruoy evres ot nageb uoy nehw ton uoy did yhW
.reh wollof ot deirt neve reven dah hadhaF
sraey owt reh gnirud
.effag eht gnirongi
.niaga tnelis llef dna ,htaerb gniredduhs rehtona ni koot ehS "…taht retfA
,dias ronrevog eht
",reh fo suoreneg yrev
,robal drah fo ecnetnes efil A
.meht teerg ot ,gnilims ,taes reh morf ylhtooms esor liatkraD ronrevoG
.sretrauq reh edistuo erow syawla ehs tekcaj citsalp dehctap eht pu piz reh gnikam
efiw reh dna radanilA htiw level eye ta reh gnittup
.staem tneluccus dna selbategev fo tsaef elbatirev a htiw nwod dedaol ,elbat dehsaw etihw
.niap dna rorret dna yoj reh gnirebmemer ,debbos dna
,elbat eht ta deraeppa erugif llat a sa ,ezorf ehS
.gnikahs reh lortnoc ot gniyrt
,dlihc nexof dezarc-flah
,seod ehs nehw tuB"
",nimreT ,siht tog ev'I"    .seye nedlog dna
,esoprup eht rof yllaicepse edisa tes lwob a ni smlap reh dehsaw hadhaF
,ecnanep fo ycrem eht
,em evigrof ton dluow flesmeht doG
.radanilA ta yrgna yrev saw ograM"
,sdnah ym ni ydob nekorb reh dleh I
,sdrow ro scipot eseht ot evitisnes er’uoy fI
,deppots sgnul dna traeh yM
,feiler dna rednow ni neht ,ynoga ni peew ot nageb I .despalloc dna
.yrenif neklis fo sebor ni depard ydob reh
,laem nexof a t'nsi sihT
,eno citenrebyc a yb decalper gnieb eye dlo reh ni detluser dah hcihw ,sracs lanogaid eerht yb dessorc eno thgir eht
,yrassecen erew tub
.suoreneg ooT .dias hadhaF
.neerikahs-hsanim mukaw dob'af ahal-lilaB
"?su htiw tae dna nwod tis esaelp uoy t'noW
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.edisni reh gnirehsu
.daeh reh gnikcud ,delbmum ehs
.eid dluow ehs ,t'ndid I fi esuaceB
.nac I sa drah sa krow ot yrt I"
.ecivres reh evael enoyna tel ton seod ehs …ehS
,mialc uoy sa kcalb sa saw traeh ruoy fI"
",snosaer elbadnatsrednu rof
.delbmuts ehs ",--diN ,sey-
,eerf eb ton lliw uoY"
eciffo ytiruces s'ynoloc eht ot troper yllacidoirep ot deriuqer saw ehS
",elbat s'liatkraD ronrevoG ta draeh I sa erecnis sa eb dluow esromer ruoy kniht ton od I
,nwod daeh reh dewob ehS
.tius gniwollof nexof owt eht htiw
,nori thguorw saw retnec eht tA
.emit tsal eht rof dlrowemoh reh tfel dah ehs nehw ,taht erofeb dna
,srennam reh tegrof ot hguone dekcohs
"?gninetsil neve uoy ereW"
N"   "?reh esufer uoy lliW"
",nevigrof saw I"   "!daed eht ot kaeps ot elba era uoy fi
.dlrowemoh nexoF eht morf detropmi seno dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.efiw sih dna rehtorb ruoy
".daed rof pu uoy nevig ecnis gnol dah nalc ruoY
",ti etagitim ot od nac I elttil si ereht raef I dna ,si ti oS"
.redluohs reh no mlap a yal ot elbat eht ssorca dehcaer ladiN   .gniveilebsid
,reh delf regna reh sa
,radanilA was uoy ,lleW" .deggurhs hadhaF "…dnuof ehs seno eht
.yrassecennu saw ti
,elbat nori thguorw eht fo tnorf ni
dna eno siht piks ot referp yam uoy
.dlihc on ma I ,oN"
pu raet seye reh gnileef ,ylwols eta ehS
.gnidnatsrednu ton
,ereh era uoy fI" .kcab tohs ehs
.emarf eht ot reh dnuob srehto eht elihw ,llits radanilA dloh ot em deredro ehs oS"
.sretrauq reh sdrawot gnidaeh
.tsal eht ta dna tsrif eht ta ,esiarp eb miH oT
.won teppup s'nomed eht saw I"
,oga sraey owt lairt reh ta neeb dah eman lluf reh draeh d'ehs emit tsal ehT
.snehctik eht morf revotfel gnihtemos teg dluoc I esoppus …I"
,yawllah eht nwod gniklaw nageb radanilA
.htaerb peed a ni werd hadhaF
.daed llef dna ynoga ni demaercs ,ograM epacse ot deirt dah ohw sinik a
gnikaeps si yllausu ehs
,nailadra eht ot revo uoy dnah ograM ydoolB did yhW"
.setalp gnivres eht morf pu detfaw sehsid nagazaw evitan nezod-flah a fo sllems suoiciled eht sa ,htuom reh ni mrof avilas dna
.emoh tog I nehw gnihtemos tae ot gniog saw I"
.tnemerugifsid eht eciton ton eno gnikam
,noisserpxe reh ni egnahc on edam liatkraD ydaL tuB
.dlrow rieht fo stresed eht ni devlove dah s'hadhaF tub
".ton did ilA elihw ,snoitca ruoy ni eciohc dna ycnega dah uoY
).kcab thguorb eb uoy llahs miH ot dna
,lleH siht gniretne esle enoemos fo aedi eht ta tpew I
,mih revo derewot ehS
.deilper yeht ",spahreP"
,dlrow thgil siht fo taht eciwt ytivarg htiw tenalp a no nrob
snoitats ecaps eht fo srodirroc eht nwod ylduorp deklaw ehs sa ,edisa mih devohs dna dehgual evah dluow ehs ,ecnO
traeh reh dnuora depparw d'ehs dnab nori dloc eht tlef hadhaF sa
neht dna ,seceip derdnuh a otni ti raet ,ydob rieht kaerb ot edam saw I
"!sraey dnasuoht a rof teppup a sa em tpek dah nomed nailadra eht fi neve
.ton erew sedarmoc reh fo ynam os nehw
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,deksa liatkraD ronrevoG
",uoy ot kaeps ot sehsiw ronrevoG ehT"   "?no gniog si tahw"
,won si tnemtaert ym 'riafnu' woh meht llet ot yrT
ruf etihw dna kcalb htiw nexiv llams a gnittimda
.selacs ynit fo sdnasuoht fo snet fo desopmoc
.deunitnoc ronrevog eht
,nomed eht ot em deef ot
ssetnuociV ronrevoG eht ot trosnoc dna efiw ,liatkraD-roliaskcalB radanilA
,em ot kaeps radanilA was I noos esuaceb ,dam llits saw I
,dega yrev eht fo elprup peed eht selacs rieht
!doG luficrem ruo fo sgnisselB"
.pu ti tfil ot tinu vargitna llams a deriuqer evah dluow
.setarip s'ograM ydaL fo eno sa
.noo'ajrut ihyali'aw umkuh lohalaW .harihkalaw aloo lif odmah lohaL .uhalliahalial ohallawohaW   "!emoh emoc ot tnaw I dna
.kniht ot emit elttil reh evag krow gnikaerbkcab ,draH
dekan saw I ,denekawa I nehW"
.lairt ym fo wonk tsum uoy
thgit seye reh tuhs hadhaF ".eerf
,ytidimuh dna taeh s'remmus etal eht ni gnitaews neeb evah dluow secaR xiS rehto eht fo ynA
yllautneve ,etaf taht depacse dah ehS
…s'tahT"   ".uoy tuoba
".ezingocer llew dluoc I smret ni ti debircsed eh
”reyarP tA“ saw sihT
,yraew dna ,ytrid dna ,dloc ma I
,noisnam eht hcaer ot ruoh na ylraen reh koot tI
.slewej dna dlog fo demaerd dah hadhaF ecnO    yad ecyoR yb
dezingocer hadhaF mohw
!taht rof pu ekam dluoc
.detcejretni radanilA ",swonk ehS"
.ratla eht morf em desaeler ogra'aM dna ,niaga detrats yeht nehT
,em koot nomed eht nehw sa lufwa sa niap ,niap tlef I nehT
ecneloiv devivrus evah ohw sretcarahc
rood eht nehw noitnetta ot pans ot ylno ,ylffurg derettum eh ",taht kcehc ot evah ll'I"   ".emoc ot dlot saw I" .deyalpsid egassem eht htiw pmoc reh pu dleh ehS .dettimda hadhaF ",wonk t'nod I"   .dednamed eh