sdnah sih ni pam a htiw regnarts a deciton I
,ylevisserpmi tsoM
!rettO retsiM"   .miws ot nageb daeh yM
,moor nommoc eht otni erom ecno dedaeh I
,ksa t'ndid eh sa tub ,si elits a tahw wonk ton thgim tsuj
.nnI eht ta moor nommoc eht ot ruoted kciuq a rof nalp a ,esruoc fo
ereht neeb dah taht srehto eht
..."   .edih dna yawa nur ot swollef sih ta gnimaercs ,sub sih rof dedaeh eh sa edistuo deohce sraor dellif-rorret siH
skcals thgirb yrev emos
.ecaf derruf-etihw sih revo lla
.htron raf eht morf semoc taht ruatonim fo dnik a s'tahT
.pihsnamkrow eht dekcehc dna
.'tlep' sih ti sllac eh
em morf tsrub swaffug ym erofeb rood eht tuo nur ot deganam I
.erauqs eht fo tsae eht ot gnitniop ,dias I ",thgiR .hO"
.ecaf sih no kool deirrow a htiw em ta nwod gnikool saw
teef sih no seohs rehtael-tnetap denihs-ylwen ylevol dah retto eht deciton I
,oob-oob rojam ylno eht fo ecnedive saw dray eht ni tniap etihw fo hctolb eguh a dna dloffacs nekorb a ,kcab eht tuO
).tisiv emoc oD .stsiruot ruo evol eW .tsej I(
"?ay dluow ,stuobaereh s'yeht fi wonk 'nedoow aY"
.ssennellus dna noitangiser fo erutxim a htiw em ta pu dekool eH
.nrecnoc ruoy rof uoy knaht dna ,llew m'I ,em eveileB"
”hsawetihW—nnI ehT tA“
lufwa gnihtemos od ot gniog saw ruatonim eht taht gniveileb ,deifirroh saw I
,seog gniyas dlo eht sa
.hsurb ym fo duorp yrev m'I dna ,ruf hsulp ,tfos
,stnap ym pu gnihctiH
.snroh ytniop dna seye llab-8 sih ekil
sgnitirw sih daer nac uoY
.doolb ruoy knird dna
doG'( gniteerg lausu ym evag dna
.siroB htiw sessem eno-oN
”hsawetihW—nnI ehT tA“
.emit siht tpecxE    .yllausu
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
!uoy htiw gnorw s'tahW !siroB"
..."   .exa revlis prahs ylsuoiciv ,gnimaelg
.rood gnigniws-llits eht ta ylknalb gnirats ,deilper siroB ",t'nac I"
"!oot ereh swoc dah syug ooy oon reven I !eeG
tnemhsinotsa fo noisserpxe dewaj-kcals a htiw
dloc yrev a htiw ssenrah sih morf dellup eh hcihw
htuom sih denepo eh tnemom ehT
.nnI enif ruo fo egami na yb til eb dluow moor eht ni setom eht dna
,)emit ym rof owt ro nioc a ro( uoy knaht a sa hcum os tuohtiw ,nehT
srehto tcerroc ot ecalp ym ton s'ti tub
semit ynam eeht etims I llahs ylirev neht ,raw fo nopaew dercas ym hctef tlahs I ,oL"
foor dehctaht eht fo edisrednu eht no tniap fo
,setnorB fo serutnevda eht gnirutaef
.moc.sussatem no ro
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
… hu –I" .eniF .eciN .lamroN
”.gob eht ni meht yrub t'nac“
.)oot taht detcepxe I(
rood eht nepo dehsup I—
,noitcif-orcim detimil-drow no neek ylralucitrap si eH
yllausu taht ssenkrad a s'tI
moor nommoc eht fo rood eht nepo dehsup I
puorg "tpmorP yadsruhT"
?tahW"   ".kcohs ni m'I"
:enim ekilnu etiuq si ruf siH
.deirc I litnu dehgual dna seenk ym no nwod llef I ,edistuO
srood eht tsap tuo depmots neht
"!yddub ,ay no dooG"
,exa sih sdloh taht ssenrah rehtael gib a dna htolcniol a sraew eh ,gnihtolc roF
.ecno rof boj elbanosaer a enod evah ot demees setnorB
… draeh tsuj I tahw eveileb t'nod I .on ,oN"
.tsiruot tsol a saw eh wenk I
sussateM yb ”hsawetihW—
,dekool setnorB etuc woh tuoba tuo gnitibbar saw tsiruot ehT
"!mih pots em pleh ot evah uoY
tsiruot eht ylno taht tnempiuqe fo tib a barg ot tuoba saw
.thgirla etiuq saw I fi em deksa eh sa
.aremac sih tuo dellup dna dethgiled dekool tsiruot ehT .emit eht lla
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.mih erofeb hsam niarg fo lwob a
sa ylhguor setalsnart taht kool railimaf taht evag setnorB
hcum ekoms t'nod I
.exa sih htiw ecnalabmi eht riaper ot deirt yllufpleh ruatonim eht dna
,elims degnaf-dekoorc ym htiw ,ruf yerg dna der lla ,ereht eb d'I
ecin evah sexof eW
tnemezama latot dna
,aedi deripsni ylralucitrap a eb ton thgim siht taht siroB nraw ,trap ym rof ,did I
,4 .loV gnaF ni
.ytnewt ot tnuoc llahs I .rettO"
.dnekeew eht revo dehsawetihw nnI eht dah dah siroB
.tekcaj dereppiz a dna
.raeb ralop a naht aneyh a ot detius erom eb dluow taht
.skooB dooG eht morf etouq nac I oS( ".doG
eht fo trap sa kcab emit emos gnitirw detrats sussateM
.etats sih ni kcab si 'llub delkceps' a erar woh dna ,'emoh kcab'
revo delbuod siroB ,retnuoc eht dniheB
-- htolcniol sih fo emos neve ,ssenrah sih fo tsom ,smra sih ,tsehc sih ,ecaf sih ,tuons sih ,snroh siH
)yb em dessap t'ndah yeht sa ,os demussa I ro(
.ylruc tahwemos dna regnol s'ti erehw
eht rof 'nikool m'I .yddub ,yaS"
,ekops hbrat ehT
.sniameR eltsaC cirotsiH
!tsiruot taht llik ot gniog s'eH
,ten.ytiniffaruf no yhpargotohp sih weiv dna
,dnalerI fo tsew dliw eht ni desaB
.efil eritne ym ni draeh reve evah I gnihtyna sa gnicanem sa dna gnillihc eciov sih
.erauqs eht ssorca dedaeh dna
.esuac eht syawla s'eH .tnih A
,enitsirp sih dna
.roolf eht otno laem sih fo emos dellips dna
sraey decnavda ym etipsed sgniht gnitseretni ynam od nac I
.allerbmu ym togrof I taht gnituohs
).llat sehcni ruof tuoba pu dedne riahc ehT
.enif saw gnihtyrevE
.doG yht htiw nioj dna
efiw hsiretto taf sih dna yug siht fo noisiv eugav a dah I
,yadretsey fo stneve eht retfa gninnips llits si daeh yM
.sdrawpu dereviuq htuom ym fo segde ehT
.llub derepmet-dab eht
).laffo morf slaem suoiciled ekam ot woh dna
sllaw lautca eht no tniap fo reyal tneced a saw ereht
,hctah rab eht yb gnidnats saw siroB .deruos dah
.ylluf ti detcepsni t'nevah I fi krow enif eht tnemilpmoc yldrah nac I ,naem I
si yrots s’yadot dna
.deedni egamad tahW
hbrat eht morf yawa lwob hcnul sih dna elbat eht dellup eh
.spil sih morf welf sdrow sih sa tsaf sa tsomla aremac sih no yawa dekcilc retto ehT
adnap a ekil dekool enivob etiruovaf ruo dias neve eh tniop eno tA
.ecaf ediw sih no kool ylwocs tnasaelpnu yrev a dna
,htolcniol sih denethgiarts
,htiw egalliv eht hguorht lanoitutitsnoc ym gnikat saw I dna
.dlrow eht revo lla morf stsiruot thguorb yllanoisacco dna
.tab llabesab sih tuo dellup ylwols dna retnuoc eht rednu dehcaer siroB
.aremac sih gnikcilc deunitnoc dna em ta gnikool tuohtiw ffo ti dekcuhs eH
ssarg eht no dna dnuorg eht no tniap deird fo selddup saw erehT
flesym fo lortnoc dloh ot deirt I
,seye ym morf sraet eht epiw ot deirt dna ria nwod deplug I
gninnirg dna ssalg a gnipiw doots siroB ,rab eht dniheB
,neercs a dna rotcejorp a htiw moor gnivil eulb dna knip eguh a ni
oga gnol fo sraw eht ni elttab otni gniog
nnI ehT tA“:yojne esaelP
"?gnitniap erew uoy ees I
.enod llew boj a no
”,meht htiw evil t'naC“ .stsiruoT
noitcartta niam s'egalliv ruo saw eltsac deniur ruO
.tnemhsinotsa dna
sraeberof enipluv suoirtsulli ym fo yna sa evarb sa—neht
ni tnew I erofeb edistuo eht dnuora deklaw I
,enizagam nocorhtnA eht ni deraeppa sah krow siH .ytiniffA ruF no
,retal taebtraeh A   ".eniN .thgiE
.yawyna tnorf eht morf taht ees t'ndluoc uoy tub
,snroh etihw dna kcalb derettaps-tniap 'setnorB morf erats dekcohs sih devom eh sa dehcnalb eH
shgual fo seires a detrons dna
,nnI dehsawetihw ylhserf eht edistuo gnidnats ,em fo semorhcadoK fo elpuoc a ekam retto eht tel dna doots I   .yob ho …    ... rutto
.erofotereh deganam reve dah eh gnihtyna naht esrow raf saw taht elbuort fo level a otni teg dna
"?buP a siht si ,yaS"
remocwen eht ta yletilop delims dna ,ytluciffid htiw pu denethgiarts I
).netfo oot od dluohs I eveileb I gniht a ton si syawrood hguorht tuo gninnur
saw sihT"!?tnuoc nac eh
elbativeni eht ffo evats dluow taht gnihtemos htiw pu emoc dluow raeb ralop eht gnipoh
,ma I sa dlo sa dna(
ecaf sih morf nwod devom ylwols aremac s'tsiruot ehT   ".eerhT .owT .enO
.deraef dah I sa dab sa flah t'nsaw tI
,yad gnirps ylrae lufthgiled a saw tI
rab eht ta sselnoitom gnidnats saw eh daetsni tub
.kool wen 'setnorB ta hgual ot ton flesym gnicarb
)'god eht dna tac eht tpecxe ,ereh lla sselb
moor nommoc eht edisni erehpsomta ehT
.ward gnol a koot dna epip ym til I
,ereht saw setnorB
!thgis a saw eh ,sdog hO
.sdrow eht esilatipac mih raeh dluoc I raews I ".sniameR
).yawa nur ot nehw gnigduj ekil—
,siroB ta ylsselpleh dekool I
.mih dniheb tuhs demmals yeht dna meht hguorht dehsarc eH
"?buP eht edistuo evitan a fo otohp a teg I nac ,yddub ,yaS"
,niaga rood tnorf eht rof hsad ot dah dna lortnoc tsol I
.gnireviuq pil ym ,dias I
;wonk uoy t'nod ,ytud ym ti redisnoc I
.deneppah tahw uoy llet em teL
,eltsac eht ot kcart-trac yddum eht tuoba mih gninraw tuoba thguoht dna
.desaelp neeb evah tsum siroB
,detcelloc flesym teg ot setunim wef a em koot tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.amard rehtona ,yad rehtonA
.esuac eht eb ot dah tahw esilaer ot lla ta troffe on koot ti dna
?I ma ,doolb ym yfitrof ot mraw gnihtemos gnikat tuohtiw yb ssap ot gniog yldrah m'I ,lleW
,)tab llabesab eht htiw lluks kciht sih revo llub eht gnikcahw sa hcus(
.moor nommoc eht ot hguorht dna
a ton dna xof a zuw eh n'fi mih ekil dekool a'dluow yppapdnarg ym dna su ekil ton dna dlo os dna
steliot edistuo eht ot tuo deraeppasid dna ecracs sevlesmeht edam dah
.hsawetihw ni derevoc lla saw ti
.sdrawkcab pets suoicsnocbus  a koot neht I dna
.erats etarebiled dna
,yaw eht yb ,droldnal eht s'eH
sdneirf dalc-retseylop taf rieht ot pirt sih fo sotohp eht gniwohs
,daeh sih fo pot eht dna sredluohs sih dnuora tpecxe
mih etalutargnoc dluoc I os hcnul sih gnivah edisni saw ruatonim eht taht gnipoh ,ni tnew I
.saw yllaer ti tahw rof esingocer dluow
.semitemos senizagam eht pu xim yeht dna rood txen thgir si pohs rebrab ehT
.gniyfirret era senizagam ’seidaL
.hbraT a si setnorB
,em rof tfel syawla s'taht kooh eht no taoc ym gnuh I retfA
raelc emaceb ti woN !sdog raed ,hO
".ti ssim t'nac uoY .dleif revolc eht fo pot eht ta s'ti dna
.rehtaew dab ni tuo gnieb tuoba gif a evig t'nseod eh dna
.toob ym fo leeh eht tsniaga lwob epip eht fo stnetnoc eht dekconk I sa
,exa sih rof mih dniheb dehcaer dna
.flesym stoob delian-boh referp I
!eltsac eht ot og ot tnaw uoY
.tsafkaerb lluf a dna peels s'thgin doog a ,seiddot toh nezod-flah a retfa neve
"?enoemos llik ot gniog si setnorB tahT
emosewa kool erus yeht t'nod
,neve ton saw gel esohw riahc nedoow a saw ti eveileb I(
.yawenal taht pu klaw setunim evif tuoba si eltsac ehT"
,trohs dna yriw erom gnieb
,desilaer I ,erom neve kcab gnirb dluow yddot toh A
,nopaew sih detfeh setnorB   ".ytnewT .neeteniN
,ruf naht riah ekil erom si tlep 'setnorB
!woc yttops siht fo scip ekat annaw I !yddub ,haN"
.cihpargoeG lanoitaN eht fo revoc tnorf eht no eb ot saw I ekil gnisop
sdnah derevoc-tniap etihw dna kcalb sih ot ,tuons etihw dna kcalb sih tsap
ylwols uoy rethguals llahs I dna exa siht htiw uoy retfa emoc llahs I nehT
nac uoy ,yllautcaf ,lleW
.srood eht rof nar dna demaercs retto eht
.modnar ta mih debmob-evid dah snoegip noillim eno ekil dekool eH
,noops nedoow sih htiw dnuora ti gnihsup saw eH
nottub eht sserp d'eH
,shtaerb peed fo elpuoc a koot I sA
.nopu-denworf s'ti os ,krowrepap artxe eht ekil t'nseod tnaegres lacol ruo tub
.enod htrae no krow sih redisnoc dna meht fo 563 evah ll'eh tniop emos tA ."selaT droW 563" meht gnillac
",setnorB ,yad dooG"
.ytilamron fo lleps eht kaerb dna tsrub em ekam dluow siroB htiw tcatnoc eye wenk I sa
.repmet dluoc sdrow tfos ym fo yna tlef I kool a ton saw sihT
.tlep sih morf ylisae os ffo emoc t'nseod ti teb ll'I dna
wow dna sevitan eht fo eno saw siht taht ecnuonna d'eh dna
dnal tnatsid a morf enoemos taht dnim ym dessorc tI
"?uoy pleh I nac woH
... ecneserp tnelovelam ,gnidoorb a mih sevig
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.hguone noos flesmih yb lla tuo taht dnif d'eh tub
.taht ekil em ta kool t'nod ,woN(
,étrof sih dnuof yllanif dah dneirf enivob ym taht desaelp gnileeF
tnedurp ti thguoht I dna ecaf sih no skool cinam railimaf sih fo eno dah siroB tub
?od llub eht dluoc egamad tahw os ,ssalg wodniw morf evomer ot ysae saw hsawetihw taht em derussa eh ,yawynA
,mih erofeb efil ot gnilbmur noitpure cinaclov eht fo erawanu yllufssilB
,kcalb tej ,oot kcalb s'tI
.sresserdriah eht ni daer seidal eht senizagam elyts eht ni ees uoy ekil
,setnorB no noitnetta ym desucof I .ylithgim
"!ay fo tser eht ees t'nac I ?llub ,pu dnats uoy nac ,yaS"
eno eta eh fi llabesab a wonk t'ndluow taht raeb ralop a elihw ,airuaT morf ruatonim a gnidaog retto na dah ew ereH .taht railuceP
.seiromem dnof kcab sgnirb dna rehtafdnarg ym fo em sdnimer occabot eht fo tnecs eht tub ,ti ekil yllaer t'nod I dna
,daeh sih no pac talf a htiw ,retto na saw regnarts ehT
.hcum oot tniop eht ruobal ot ton
.lufrewop yrev dna ykcots dna gib s'eH
,ecalp lausu sih ni
.nepo gnuh waj sih dna
.tnemirrem ym morf edis ym ni hctits lufniap a teg ot deganam I dna
.ni flesym gnidloh fo troffe eht morf pu gniretaw erew seye ym sa noisiv ym raelc ot yldipar knilb ot dah I
rehtruf elbat eht dehsup setnorB
etelpmoc ni renroc eht ot revo depag dna
,denrecnoc gnikool
hcrop eht otni decnuob eh
.seye ym morf sraet tsal eht depiw dna retsum dluoc I sa rennam a yldneirf sa ni dennirg I
,sussateM ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
tas hcihw rednu ,duolcrednuht eht ot pu deklaw dna
.daeh ym ni revo dna revo ’enif si gnihtyreve‘ gnitaeper yb
.srood dna swodniw eht fo ssalg kciht eht no
,dnah eno fo selkcunk eht no pu depporp daeh sih
.raeb ralop dlo hguot ytterp a s'eh dna
.yldipar yawa dekcab I
.ti no dnapxe t'ndid I
yrots eht ni deraeppa ylsuoiverp ohw ruatonim ffurg a
desaeced tra uoht litnu
stolps saw ereht dna )taht detcepxe I(
.goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef osla ,”nnI ehT tA“
.ekatsim yb retnirp sih no yllanoisacco dna
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ni dekool eh sa yllacitsaisuhtne deilper eh
esuba lasuops dna sredrum tuoba lla s'tI
,ssorc ot deen uoy elits eht ta tsopngis a s'erehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sussateM yb
tolb lanoisacco eht ylno dna
era sruatonim wef woh ,saw eh euqinu woh
,bup erem a sa debircsed gnieb nnI devoleb sih raeh ot evol dluow siroB .deddon I
,spil ym morf gnignah epip eht
.desuac eh egamad tsetal eht rof tnemyap ni krow lautca eht od ot dlot neeb dah setnorB ,netfo os elbuort desuac dah eh esuaceB
... kcab tuo tniap etihw fo aera gib eht dna dloffacs nekorb eht—
.redluohs s'tsiruot eht no dnah a gnittup ,dessih I "!won oG