,)dah eh yenom eht lla saw ti taht gnivorp(
.eugnot knip gib taerg sih htiw pu meht dekcil dna
.noitcefrep otni loots taht dluom ot sraey net koot tI
.tlas ssendoog-ot-tsenoh nialp deedni saw tI
.yadnuS gnitrops a retfa gninrom yadnoM eht no ylralucitrap
,emussa ot dah I ,siroB
.retnuoc ynihs eht otno dlog diuqil suoicerp eht gnihsols ,duht yvaeh a htiw nwod ssalg ym tes
.ecalp tsrif eht ni hctid a ni pu dne ylbaviecnoc dluoc nosrep eno ylnO
,enizagam nocorhtnA eht ni deraeppa sah krow siH
".nwot ni yawa erew uoy elihw ,emithcnul yadseuT tsal
.'laineg' dellac eb reve raeb ralop ffurg eht dluoc ron
.nerhterb gnilkraps sti fo dimaryp a otno ylluferac ssalg sih gnicalp ,delworg siroB
,noitisop siht otni mih tog dah
,emas eht hcum ytterp erew seton dna yenom ruo taht desilaer I
"!NOITNETTA OT DNATS"
.ekops I sa tsuj moor nommoc eht ni emaceb noitasrevnoc eht teiuq dna
,rab eht dniheb sevlehs ssalg eht bmilc ot detpmetta neht eh ,yltnerappA
.aedi ym rof tnemeerga yrrem fo lluf saw rab eritne eht demees ti ,htuom ym tfel dah sdrow eht dah renoos oN
.moor ytpme eht dnuora gnirutseg ,niaga desuap I ".tol
,dilos nezorf erew srood tnorf edistuo selttob kliM
,stsif sih fo hcaer nihtiw kcab deppets dna
.elims a ni eson ym delknirw dna draknat sih ta nwod dekool I ,noitasrevnoc ekam ot gniyrT
.nmelos ecaf sih ,derettum eh
.sussateM yb ”feeB detlaS—nnI ehT tA“
,saedi ytrap hsidnaltuo erom dna erom htiw mih gnidrabmob erew snortap neknurd yppah esohw raeb ralop a fo yaw eht fo tuo peek ot gnipoh ylteiuq dna ,deugirtnI
.yarps eht htiw em gnihcnerd
,nwo ym lla deredisnoc I gep laiceps eht no meht gnuh dna sreyal ynam ym ffo deleep I elihW
.tab llabesab s'siroB yb denaeb tog eh nehw detrawht saw
.noitseggus eht nekat dah eh yldab woh tsuj desilaer dna yddot ym fo pis a koot
.erofeb thgin eht eman s'ttaM denoitnem dah I hsiw ylno I
.ecalp lausu ym ni tas dna ,krow noitarotser eht fo ytilauq eht no siroB detnemilpmoc ,ni delbboh I
teerts eht no tuo
,dne no saw ruf siH
.elpoep ynam oot htiw tseretni tlas—
.reehc eslaf htiw dias I "!siroB ,gninrom dooG"
.dedulcni flesym
dneirf ym fo mrof gnirebmul eht dettops I
,em revo emac gnileef gniknis A
,retnuoc eht dniheb deppord dah ohw ,siroB dna dehgis I
"–deneppah evah thgim tahw ees ot gninnigeb m'I hguoht
.peelsa dnuos ,smra sih ni deldarc daeh sih ,hctid eht ni ylleb sih no gniyl saw
,siht tseggus ot enutrofsim eht dah I yhw wonk ylno sdog ehT
,emit emas eht tA .laer dna tneced
dna serusaem eht morf denrut ylwols eH
.peekrab eht fo tnow eht era
esiwrehto ro lanoitnetni—noitcurtsed rof tnahcnep a sah eH
!snroh sih dnuora ti deit dna htolcniol sih ffo dellup
.ton era ew gnihtyreve si eH
.niaga reve ,rehto yna ro ,em yb desu eb reven dluow ti taht
.emoh og ot dediced I
dna–nekorb saw eno tsal eht nehw yenom ecnarusni eht ot sknaht ,ssel on
;su fo htob rof sknird deredro ruatonim eht sa kool yci na setnorB evag eH .ecaf sih dna
.raelc sgniht emos teg
"?knurd uoy sekam siht -- he -- dnA"
",lohocla knird ton od I" .deggurhs neht
,em ta yllacizziuq dereep eH
.flesmih dnuora ti depparw dna htolcniol sih pu dekcip neht
mlap sih no meht tup eH
.hctah eht ta deraeppa ecaf enivob ylrus A
.ereht llits saw I desilaer dah eh fi sa ,em ta delrans dna pu kcab doots
.tnatropmi s'tahT
,doog era sela sih ,llitS
.dias evah uoy tahw fo emos htiw eussi ekat I"
erew ti morf stiforp eht dna ,raey yreve dna hcae eno dah ttaM ,nnI eht nur ot ereh emac uoy erofeB
.yldetnetnoc gnirons saw eH
.sgnigdol nekat dah eh hcihw ni nrab eht morf daor eht pu gniklats setnorB
,tlas no lluks sih fo tuo dna ,hah-ooh eht deniojer setnorB
,ertnec eht nwod thgir dekcarc saw
trofmoc eht rof dedaeh
,ylffits deddon eH
.tsal ta em ot ekops eh taht ,tbuod on ,ecaf ym no esirprus eht htiw dna
.nwonk tseb era ylimaf sih hcihw rof cigam eht enod dah ssoR taht tpecxe
"?taht ekil dloc ton uoy erA !setnorB"
.ecaf ediw sih gnimarf snroh ,daeh sih gnilgna ,ylpmis dias eh
,weiv tsrif eht ta dnilb enog ydaerla t'ndah I fI
.hsinif em tel ,oN"   .mih pots ot wap eno pu dleh I dna kaeps ot htuom sih denepo eH
.dnuorg eht no drah yal eci dna wons ,dnuora dellor retniw-dim nehW
.hctid eht otni nwod dna daor eht ssorca ,rood tnorf eht tuo
?efil ruoy ni knurd neeb evah reven uoy"
... ro reeb yb detceffa ton ma I
,hctal-kooh a htiw desolc dleh ,srood llams owT
GNIHT–taht–tahT"
,rennam erutam dna thgirhtrof a ni noitseuq a mih deksa dna ssalg gnissim eht ta detniop I taht uoy llet ot evol dluow yleniuneg I
".raey siht gnirpS fo yaD tsriF eht rof ereh od a fo tib a evah yllaer dluohs ew
",xoF dneirf ,ssenlufthguoht ruoy etaicerppa od I"
.doolb eht rits dluow taht thgis a saw eH
sraew enoyreve ,egalliv ruo nI
,teef ym ot em depleh eh ,drow a tuohtiW
,thgir neht ,tfel dekool eH
,ylmraw flesym desserd I
"?tfel I retfa deneppah yltcaxe tahw ,siroB ,esaelP ...oS"
.ekatsim yb retnirp sih no yllanoisacco dna ,4 .loV gnaF ni
.dedoolf tog sesuoh rieht fi od dluow yeht tahw derednow I
w ehT ?sirob-B ?siroB
tsrif ta elttil a—
.htnom hcae noitar tlas llams a nevig
,yawa mra sih dehsup
.elbuort ni saw I wenk I
ecitsuj od yaw yna ni dluoc sdrow elpmis ym kniht t'nod I
,moor nommoc dedworc eht hguorht yaw ruo dehsup ew sa eh dias ",I"
.desaelp lla ta kool t'ndid setnorB
thgieh lluf ym ot pu flesym dellup I
.doog ton saw sihT
,emoh daeh ot dediced I
,siroB ,sneppah os ti dnA
morf tnew dna suoretsiob tog eH
dna regnif gnitniop sih dewollof I
.lla ta em ot kaeps t'ndid dna sessalg gnipiw deunitnoc siroB
,revo em dekconk eh tsaf os pu tog eH
.gnitnub ekil snroh sih neewteb deit saw htolcniol siH
.elbat eht no stnetnoc eritne eht dellips dna gnidnib eht fo tonk eht denepo
,rab eht no denael siroB
.em erofeb decalp saw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .god.ecioveht
,dliw si setnorB
kcits ym debbarg
ton–su dnuora yletaidemmi elpoep fo kcal a saw ereht ,moor dedworc a roF
eht fo trap sa kcab emit emos gnitirw detrats sussateM ,dnalerI fo tsew dliw eht ni desaB
niadsid tcefrep fo kool a em gnitoohs ,draknat sih fo egde eht revo em ta derats eH ".elpoep
,ereht tuo s'taht tehctah elttil tnulb eht htiw dehsdoow eht ni doow eht fo lla tilps ot enoemoS
.ti deen uoy nehw nepo s'ti dna tneced si nni sih
,ytpme dna dedracsid saw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.srood eht no deremmah edis rehto eht no enoemos nehw ksa ot tuoba tsuj saw I
).mehA( ?snroh eerht htiw ruatonim hgih toof-thgie na nekawa eno seod woh oS
.yrwod a sa esu ot sraey dna shtnom rof ti devas meht fo lagurf tsom eht dna ,nioc rof
ssalc on dna yticirtcele on htiw tnemhsilbatse hguor ,ysaerg a—
?llaw a no hgih os doowerif rof hctah a ekam enoyna dluow yhW
.htraeh s'siroB ediseb
.s'yppup a sa knip sa tnew ylbaborp srae ym edisni niks thgil eht dna
eht sa ,lausunu taht lla
,yradnegel saw yenrab gnitluser eht ,stnuocca lla yB
egatnecrep rellams a dna ,sedarmoc rieht htiw tlas rieht derahs ,dedda eh ,srehto emoS
,sraluger fo werc yeltom a
ylbaborp ,ffo demrots dna derevocer eh litnu mih dednet dna
.ssalg eht tuohtiw ,retaw toh fo ssalg a tsuj teg ylbaborp d'I ,won llifer a rof deksa I fi wenk I
.tnemezama ni dnuora depag I sa taorht ym ni thguac psag dekcohs yM
,swap ym pu tup dna
.nnI eht ta thgif gib a saw ereht decnuonna dna—
,evisnefed emaceb dna edutitta ym yb kcaba nekat saw eH
,dessih I "!setnorB"
!ecalp tsrif eht ni woc nmad taht ni thguorb UOY"
.tros eht fo gnihton saw ti ,citeop sdnuos ti hguohtlA
,gnilbmert saw I eciton t'ndid eh gnipoh dna dluoc I sa gnirussaer sa eciov ym gnikam
.kaeps t'ndid raeb ralop eht taht deifsitas ylsuoiruc saw dna htaerb ym rehtag ot tnemom a koot I
.noziroh eht no egnaro fo tnih a naht erom a htiw
,dnats ot desu rab eht dniheb rorrim ssalg eht erehW .depsag
tnulb dna esraoc saw egaugnal siH
,ylluferac ti denepo dna dnabtsiaw sih morf gnuh yllautibah taht hcuop llams eht no nepo droc eht deggut ,deffim ,setnorB
,nrob saw eh yad eht sa dekan
.ytiniffA ruF no puorg "tpmorP yadsruhT"
.saw eh erehw setnorB gnivael ,rood eht dekcol dna swodniw eht pu dedraob
,elag eht otni gnola delffuhs I sa sraey ynam ym fo eno yreve tlef I
;ygolonhcet htiw dellif dlrow a ni xof ega-eznorb a ekil si eH
.sevolc eht llems tsomla dluoc dna ,yddot
.roolf eht derettil llits taht selttob nekorb eht fo stnetnoc eht htiw deraems ertsul yssolg sti dna
,enif neeb evah dluow gnihtyrevE
,dedlof smra ,gnittis saw ruatonim eht erehw
melborp SIH tuoba enoyreve dlot UOY dnA
emac–!sgniht lla fo–ti woh
,elbisivni saw I dedneterp dna nwod srae ym tup I
.deen ot mees I peels ssel eht ,teg I redlo eht taht dnuof ev'I
).taef siht deganam eh woh lla ta noitanalpxe yna dah t'nevah I(
si ruatonim eht ,trohs nI
,deifsitaS   ."ereht os"
.deneffitsnu sgel ym ecno thgirla tlef I dna
,ecnartne eht ta spets eht debmilc I sA
ssalc fo hcuot tsal taht ti evig ot selttob sknird eht lla dehsams
.drows nit paehc sih fo sevlah htob yb dewollof ,wodniw eht hguorht og ot tsrif eht saw noil eht dna
sdrawkcab deppets I
)sruatonim fo hcnub a rof nuon evitcelloc thgir eht s'taht fi(
.yddot toh ym rof elttek eht no dehctiws neht
dluow yeht taht rehto hcae ffo stib gnippohc nuf hguone evah thgim
,drow a tuohtiw yawa denrut siroB
.dloc ylsuoiciv tub ,yrd dna thgirb saw gninrom gniwollof ehT
.ezoob ot noisreva sih tuoba dneirf ym dezziuq I
dehcuot yleniuneg saw I
,renroc raf eht ot deriter dna ssalg ym koot I ,truh elttil a tsuj dna
.shtnom xis lluf a rof tub
.elbuort gnisuac dna sgnos gnignis ,nwot dnuora gnireggats
,tsenoh ylgnissarrabme si eh taht ekil I dna
,reklat a naht renetsil a erom era uoy taht snaem yllausu droldnal a gnieB
,wodniw eht tuo setnorB gnignilf yb ffo dengis dna
,elbbab tnerehocni erom emos dewolleb
,sdroldnal fo tsednik eht neeb reven sah ,yas tsum I ,siroB
.eciov detsiwt ylbirroh a ni ekops dna ,nam nekorb a
,yenoh dna tsaot fo ecils a dna eeffoc fo puc a retfA
.ni uoy llif ot ,sdrawretfa tog I noitamrofni emos htiw uoy rof ti esirammus ll'I
.snioc revlis evif ro ruof tuo gnikcip
.stceffe-lli gnileef tuohtiw rouqil fo tnuoma yna knird nac
,noitcif-orcim detimil-drow no neek ylralucitrap si eH
retaw 'setnorB tlas ot
,retaw hserf htiw draknat latem a dellif
eno rehtona fo thguoht ym
htolcniol rehtael sih naht rehto gnihton gniraew ,tooferaB
,duorp ylbaifitsuj neeb gnol dah siroB hcihw fo ,retnuoc rab ynagoham ehT
.feileb dnoyeb dessarrabme
,kcab elihw a ereh krow ot desu taht sraguoc eht fo nisuoc A
,hctid eht fo tuo debmilc I
",tlas eht rof sa dnA"
.ereh gnidaeh saw eh sa
.yad suoiverp eht dneirf dlo na htiw dah I noitasrevnoc a derebmemer ylneddus I dna ,em fo retteb eht tog feileR
,ti fo noisrev rellams a
"!thgin tsal siht lla detrats uoy"
.desopxe dna dloc ,yppah ,lufecaep
.nik nwo rieht rettab ot no gniog erofeb ,tsrif
,dias I ",siroB raed yM"
,segdurg ,stoir ,sthgif rab ,sknurD
.edisni kcab teg ot hguone doog tsuj saw tI
.ynam taht lla wonk t'nod I hguoht
)noitnem ton llahs I seman esohw ,ereh dnuora evil ohw elpoep niatrec ekil tsuj( emoS
.htrow saw ti lla rof ti deklim ylsuoicsnocbus I dna ,em ot enod evah dluoc siroB
.dniheb tfel saw drows ykcat siH
.egalliv eht dnuora klaw gninrom ylrae lausu ym rof tuo dedaeh dna
.ytivitca na ni degagne
nnI ehT tA“ saw sihT
.ecnelis eht ekorb eh ,esuap a retfA
toh ecin a rof gnignol yllaer saw I sa os erom eht lla
.tol siht gniwonk
mih ediug esnes nommoc stel reven eh dna—
erew–naem I ,sruatonim eht lla
.'smelborp nam' htiw meht rehtob ot thgir eb ton dluow ti dna siht gnidaer seidal eb thgim ereht sa ti no dnapxe ton llahs I
.seitrap tuoba klat siht lla detrats UOY
.sih fo seye kcalb dilos esoht htiw
.knird ym ni sevolc ro ragus nworb on saw erehT
erom dna siht fo lla ;steliot eht ni selpuoc gnitalupoc
.'ratS eloP' eht rof gnikool
,erom dna erom neht—
.ecnayonna htiw deffuh dna tuons sih nwod ylsuoirepmi dereep eH
em nwohs dah eh hcuop tlas elttil yneet eht dna
,rab eht dniheb doots siroB   ".lausunu gnihton
daeherof ym dettam taews fo kcils A
.drows ynihs hsalf a htiw epyt lufrewop gib a
,ruoloc–noisivelet wen a
.raf oot pets a saw sihT
dreh neknurd a fo eye s'dnim ym ni noisiv errazib a htiw em gnivael ,syad fo elpuoc tsrif eht ni lla ti desu
.rood eht no deremmah dna ,nnI eht ot revo dedaeh
.gniknilb tuohtiw ecaf 'setnorB otni yltcerid dekool dna smra sih dedlof ,ylffits htolc sih dedlof eH
htreb ysoc ym fo
.mih tuoba das gnihtemos s'ereht ,llitS
,dneirf enivob gib ym ni tsurt fo kcal s'droldnal eht tuohtiw od dluoc yllaer I
,nehctik sih ni hcaorkcoc a sa emoclew sa saw I fi sa em ta nwod dekool dna rood eht denepo siroB nehw dna ,denettalf srae ym
.rae sih otni dluoc I sa duol sa deraor neht
".od uoy ekil ,stirips morf ro
.mih ksa og uoY .doog
,pihs denodnaba slacol ehT
hctah eht fo edis rehto eht morf gniraews dna doow gnippohc fo dnuos ehT
.lufrednoW .nnI eht etisoppo
renroc sih ni setnorB gnivael
,evloser ym deleets ,nepo rood eht dehsup I
,gniliec eht no detnuom saremac ytiruces eht fo eno—ti dnuof eH
.)gniht dab a si taht dna(
,desaelp ylgnimees ,deddon eH
eht ot mih dael ro ksa ton did I
.dloc siht ni hctid a ni gniyl eb reve dluoc wenk I nosrep eno ylnO
.detacixotni teg ot tnaw ton od I esuaceb ton si ti ,ksa uoy erofeB"
.mih koohs dna redluohs sih debbarg I
noitseggus eht rof ytilibisnopser lluf tpecca I
.teef ym yb elddup yci na fo tuo gnikcits
.deknat uoy teg ro ecin etsat t'ndid ti tpecxe
aedi on evah llits I .nnI
sredistuo morf egalliv rieht dnefed syawla lliw yeht ,knabyrreF ehT fo snoillacspar eht tuoba yas nac uoy revetahW
.xof dlo ,devlos smelborp eerhT"
.soahc rof ytinutroppo tserem eht neve s'ereht nehw
.uoy llet nac I ,emoclew tsom dna od ot mih rof gniht lausunu na
.snroh dah hctam sih tub
.ti tuoba wonk ot ton klof emos rof retteb eb thgim ti taht gnisilaer tuohtiw ffuts eht ot noitcaer—
,hctam sih tem yllanif dah
"R'H PEELS N'YRT ER'EW PURRUHS"
nwonk reve ev'I eno-on ekil stca eH .reve—
... tehctah suoicerp sih fo gnikaeps dnA
"?llub ,eseht rof yap ot yenom evah uoY"
,revo dehcaer eh sa dekrims siroB
re—sih denialpxe setnorB"
.ereh tnereffid s'ti tub ,dnuora ffuts eht fo hcum evah t'nod uoy erehw ,emoh ta melborp gib a eb t'ndluow taht erus m'I"
..." ,yddot toh deniur ym morf gnisir sruopav eht deffins dna ssalg ym sdrawot denael eh "...
.ytrap yadiloH gnirpS a rof mih sserp ot deunitnoc taht snortap eht ta gniwolleb siroB yb derepmet
,ylteiuq dedifnoc eh
elihw a rof pu mih tuhs dna
.ecivda sih deksa netfo dna ttaM detcepser eh sa
.tcejbus eht deppord dna
,enoyna llet t'ndluohs eh taht yawa thgir mih dlot I
tey dna ;segasuas pmulp dna
,eloh egral a dah
"!niaga ereh ni gnimoc REVE ,reven si
.meht gninioj sreilp evitimirp fo riap llams a
,ffirdim sih revo ti werht dna daeh sih fo eerf htolcniol sih dellup I
.eno gnisuora na eb ot deraeppa ti dna
.yad doog a eb dluow ti ekil gnikool ton saw sihT
,syaw sih tif ti ekam ot elcsum dna retsulb htiw seirt eh hguoht
.ti deppis dna snioc emos revo dednah I
,noil eht no gnipoows ,rood niam eht ni tsrub draoh ehT
.niaga thgir eb reven dluow loots eht thguoht I dna yrtneprac fo egdelwonk elttil a dah I .wonk t'nod I
,denialpxe eh ,elpoep siH
.dnik sih ni tseretni ym htiw
si yrots s’yadot dna
.nepo rood tnorf eht dleh yldnik eh sa ylevissimsid daeh sih koohs eH
"!raey txen eht rof gniog su peek ot
fo enO .deriter eh litnu droldnal eht saw ttaM ".mih
,wodniw eht fo tfel saw tahw yas I dluohs ro ,wodniw ehT
",detacixotni neeb evah I"
,eb ylbissop ti dluoc esle ohw rof ,setnorB
.dloc gnizeerf eht ni
,sevots eht gnikots
.hctid eht ni ytuooM gnipeelS htiw od ot gnihtyreve evah ot dah tI
.mih ediseb hcneb eht no nwod tas I os
syawla–dehcnuh sredluohs s'siroB
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.elam dedoolb-der yna ekil
,woh–deriaper yltrepxe neeb dah loots dlo ym taht ees ot
.etibtsorf ytsan emos dah ylbaborp dna thgin lla tuo neeb dah eh taht em tih ylneddus tI !saw eh erehW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.sruobhgien ruo ot ylbaima tahc dna secnef ruo revo nael eW .setnorB toN
.efil egalliv fo trap a eb ot yaw yreve dna hcae ni sliaf eh
.yad yreve dna hcae ytluciffid htiw laed yeht dna
mre—ruoy erahs t'ndid uoy fi retteb eb thgim ti kniht I"
,etaicerppa dluow nwot elttil ruo fo srehgrub eht fo ynam tnelat a saw siht taht flesym ot thguoht I
.ecaf yepod ,yppah sih ta dekool dna hctid eht otni ylregnig derebmalc I
moor nommoc eht fo kcerw eht otni kcab enilef suoicsnocnu eht dellup siroB
.dlrow elttil tcefrep sih brutsid ot gnihtyna ekil t'nseod siroB
,noil suoicsnocnu eht no dednal eh erehw
egalliv eht fo dne rehto eht ta bup rehto eht ,knabyrreF ehT ot nwod nar
gniyas fo yaw sih
.erons gnilttar a ot ffo dedaf dna
,retnuoc dehctarcs eht no tsif etihw gib sih dednuop eh sa taps eh ",xof dlO"
.flesym ot nwot eht dah I ekil tlef ti
,tsal eht ot ti dnefed ot troffe na ni tnuom sti morf ti deppir dna
.hcum oot mih gnilir tuohtiw ssorca tniop eht teg ot gniyrt ,dias I ",ti naem I"
.erusaelp elpmis sih deivne I timda I
.dnilb saw I hsiw em edam taht gnihtemos was I neht dna ,gniod saw nosrep eno taht tahw ees ot revo deirruh I
"!eb tsum ti efil roop a tahW
,gnilbmurG   ".thgir ,haeY ?tlaS"
.rehto eht morf exa sih fo dne eno wonk t'nseod eh taht ruonoh fo selpicnirp desilaedi sih ni pu depparw os dna
... gnihgual cinam s'siroB yb dehctam ylno saw
.eugnot ym no niarg elgnis a decalp dna ,ylsuoituac ni regnif elttil ym deppid I ".ti
.hgis elttil a evag I
".uoy ot gnihtemos od ot enoyna ekil t'ndluow I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
)og uoy ereht tub ,raeb ralop desitamuart ylsuoires dna yrgna yltnecsednacni na ot nosirapmoc ni hcum taht lla ton(
.drows nekorb a dna
,flesmih htiw desaelp os saw eH
.selppit etiruovaf ruo fo gnikam eht ni 'deniur'
,dewaffug dna detrons llub ehT
.noitauqe eht fo tuo sregalliv eht evael
sussateM yb ”feeB detlaS—
.del ti erehw tuo dekrow I
:trons elttil a gnivig ,ees ot raeb eht rof tuo meht dleh dna
.raen oot teg yeht fi yawa snur dna kaeps yeht nehw daeh sih stlit eH
.em egludni dluow eh tbuod I
si siht ekil gnineve yllihc A
,htolcniol sih fo dnabtsiaw eht morf hcuop yenom sih deggut eh
.riaper dnoyeb nekorb sehcneb
.em ediseb llaw kcab eht no hctah elttil ddo na deciton I ,neht tsuJ
.ragus nworb dna sevolc
,deppir snoihsuc ,deyortsed sriahc ,sselgel dna derettab erew selbaT
em ot ti detseggus ohw ttaM saw ti
,ten.ytiniffaruf no
meht fo 563 evah ll'eh tniop emos tA
hguoht tub ,won tuoba emoclew eb yllaer dluow yddot toh ecin a dna
,seidal ,gninrom eht ni ylrae saw tI
.gnihtyna tsomla od dluoc siroB ,etats sih nI
exa eht laets ot tpmetta s'flow knabyrreF A
?wodniw eht ot-t deneppah tahw-hW .heh
.yb tnew setunim eht sa deilpitlum syenmihc modnar morf nmuloc ykoms lanoisacco eht tub ,tey pu erew elpoep weF
.ngis dab a
.flesmih seirrac eh yaw eht ekil I
.enod htrae no krow sih redisnoc dna
,moor eht morf nar I .doog toN
.wodniw eht tuoba mih ziuq ot detpmetta I
,peelsa llef dna ni llef neht ,hctid eht ot revo dereggats
.gnirtsward ynit a htiw
.moor nommoc eht otni siroB dewollof dna
s'teL   .won os did I
,yrros–elttac eht lla woh dna ,morf emac eh yrtnuoc eht tuoba no dna no gnilttar
,sevolc dna ragus nworb htiw etelpmoc ,yddot toh A
.secneirepxe hcir dna sraey ym fo eno gnittifeb sa
,neht em ot lla ti denialpxe eH
ecivda sekat reven eH
.mih ta syawedis kool yeht fi meht rethguals ot seirt eH
,siht sa cisab sa gnihtemos no decaps gnitteg fo tpecnoc eht derednop I
,detnioppasiD
moor yrev siht ni
.retaw toh ni denword ,yeksihw fo erusaem a tsuj saw tI
.ksa ot deen t'ndid yllaer I   "?wodniw-
,stnioj ym morf sllihc eht esahc dluow yeksihw toh a taht gnikniht
.yaw eht wonk uoY
.si semitemos ti sa edur ,rennam sih ekil I .setnorB ekil I
"!eceip noitasrevnoc a sa noitaroced wen ecin a dna
.selbmahs a saw ecalp eht–enecs eht ot
.syad-yap no toir a era dnalemoh sih ni sesuoh-ela eht enigami I
,nwot fo tuo morf noil emos htiw wor gnizalb a otni flesmih tog eh nehT .mih 'gniruonohsid'
,exa revlis egral railimaf yrev a gnuh won ereht
,od uoy sa skeew xis rof tsuj ton dnuorg eht no wons evah ew ,ereh fo htron raf ,dnalemoh ym nI
,yldezad tahwemos dna ,digir doots dna
.llaw talf a ylremrof saw tahw otni tuc neeb dah
detrats enoemos ,emoh tnew I retfA
,tnetnoc dekool ruatonim ehT
.tew s'eh nehw lufwa sllems eH
".retteb etsat ti ekam ot doof ruo no ti elknirps tsuj ew ... ees I"
,ssalg ym deniard dna dehgis I "...
.su neewteb kcits gniklaw ym gnidloh
,mih ot klat ot htuom ym denepo I
,nwad eulb thgil a gnivael revo nwolb dah mrots ehT
.tnemegduj retteb ym etipsed ,dehgual I   ".tlas htiw"
.sreknird sa tnelat rieht egludni neve t'nod nik sih dna setnorB tuB
yloh dna doog s'taht lla fo eman eht ni tahw gnirednow ,sreksihw ym gnillup ,mlap-ecaf a did I timda I
.dehcaorppa eh sa dellac I
"!sgniht lla fo TLAS ydoolb htiw
.keew doog a neve ton ebyaM
.exa ym tnaw I dna"
,enivob denniks-kciht eht tuoba did eh ekil tlef siroB yhw yltcaxe dootsrednu I dnoces-
oOo   .repmet a ni siroB dna
nnI ehT tA“:yojne esaelP
renroc a otni setnorB hsup
nocab fo srehsar gniyrf
.airuaT morf yawa raf ,raf nwot a ni evil ot deveiler yrev tlef I ylnedduS
neht raeb ralop ehT
,ssoR deman mrow elttil ykaens a
"?setnorB ,uoy nioj I
,lla ti tuoba erom elttil a thguoht I sa tub
.troffe eht ni exa sih gniogrof neve
.moor eht dnuora yliffuh gniralg
.niaga ssenisub rof denepo nnI eht erofeb keew lluf a saw ti dnA
,emoclew regnol on eman ym dna ,od ot esle elttil htiW
.egnartS ?dehsdoow ehT
htiw–yddot toh a denwod dah eh fi sa tsuj ,kcab denael eH
.desilivic sevlesruo llac eW
.ylper ni tnurg yrgna na tog I
.troppus a sa kcits gniklaw ym esu ot dah I dna ,em rof suorehcaert gniklaw edam teerts denots-elbboc eht no ecI
.detaicerppa eb dluow sessenkaew ruo fo gnidnatsrednu elttil a os ,llub a saw eh lla retfa dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.esrow ot dab morf tog sgniht nehT
edalb a htiw noil nwonknu na dna exa na htiw ruatonim knurd a taht gnimussa ylthgir
tilps a roF .dlihc a saw I hguoht sa daeh ym fo pot eht no em dettap neht
.elbuort tub gnihton
... ees uoy ,tlas ehT
,niaga srood eht tuhs dna retaw pat fo draknat a ni mih dessap siroB ".exa
yldas deton dna loots lausu ym ot sirbed eht ssorca yaw ym dekcip I
'yralas' rieht dlos
liat sih fo dne eht ot deit saw hcuop yenom siH
!ekas s'nevaeh rof ,doof evres yeht nehw ereh selbat eht no srekahs tlas neve s'erehT
,dneirf a llac I ohw ,setnorB tem I
.dnim ym deretne gnihtemoS
.tniop eht ot dna trohs saw elat ehT
... livicnu ,hsikaerf
,evid nwo rieht fo sdradnats eht gnihcaorppa gnihtemos ot moor nommoc elbon eht decuder gnivah ,werc knabyrreF ehT
mlap sih otni slatsyrc wef a deruop ylluferac setnorB
.kcab sih otno revo llor saw
.nnI ehT ni llub oN
,doog saw gniog eht elihw deunitnoc I
.mih dnats t'nac I nehw stnemom era ereht
.owt ro hgual a evah dna knird a pus ,gnos a gnis ,nray a llet nac uoy erehw–mraw ecalpemoS
.ecaf sih no elims deifsitas a
.moc.sussatem no ro
.seidal dlo elttil rof nepo srood dloh eW
,htraeh eht ni gnizalb yltnenamrep erif a dah nnI s'siroB
.nepo meht gnuws dna  ,kooh eht dehctalnu
,yltalf dias eh ",retaw tnaw I"
fo meht gnisucca dna tsehc eht ni elpoep gnikop dna dnuora gnipmots ot renroc sih morf gniwolleb
,taht naht regnorts gnihtemos tnaw t'nod uoy erus uoy erA"
,depmuts eb ot deraeppa eH
.xof dlo ,od uoy ekil dloc leef ton od"
.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
.os od ot detnaw I fi erus t'nsaw I sserdnu fo etats sih ni dna ,mih ekaw t'ndluoc I
,nerdlihc rieht fo seye eht morf peels gnipiw
.nosaer emos rof ,nwod meht derats eh nehw denialpmoc reve eno-on tey
.em ot tuo ti dleh dna ti denepo eH
.ti etsat" ,dias eh ",tlaS"
.llih eht pu dedaeh bom eht dna yawa thgir deitpme ecalp eht ,esruoc fO
did eh lla dna ,kcits gniklaw ym htiw sbir eht ni drah llub toidi eht gnikcahw devlovni htnevele eht tub ,did I sgniht net txen eht otni teg t'now I .noitom a toN
.ti hsup t'ndid I
,trihs sih dehctam taht htolc etihw-wons a htiw sessalg gnihsilop
.pu depparw llew woh rettam on em fo tuo htmraw eht dekcus dniw rettib ehT
.droldnal eht dna llub knurd-tlas eht
,deneppah tahw fo
dewolleb hctid eht morf eciov a neht ,ecaf ym ni rood eht demmals siroB
naC"   .ereht refas eb thgim ti derugif I
niarg doog fo etsaw eht naomeb ot no tnew eH
.derab erew hteet sih dna dliw erew seye sih
.tab llabesab sih tuo koot siroB
.srae ym revo drah nwod deffuts pac derettab dlo ym dna fracs etiruovaf ym ni depparw ecaf ym
- hcuop eht fo shtped eht morf meti tsal eno eht dellup ylluferac eH
.ti mrifnoc ll'eH"
.noisseforp sih ot eurt saw raeb etihw gib eht dna
.rits neve t'ndid eH "!pu ekaw"
.revo-deci erew selddup ehT
.ecaf sih no elims detnetnoc a
yhpargotohp sih weiv dna sgnitirw sih daer nac uoY
,noitcerid rieht ni nworht enutrofsim yna ssel ro erom dnatshtiw ot elba ,hcnub ydrah a era sdroldnaL
,daeh ym morf thguoht yhtrownu taht koohs I tub
.tniop sti tuo krow ot deirt I sa denworf I
.deirrow evah t'ndluohs I
.ereh noitarbelec gnirpS a evah ew taht
.ecnahc eht dah I erofeb daor eht nwod depmots dna hctid eht fo tuo debmilc eh tub
.sehtolc deroliat ylecin
,dna mih dnoyeb si taht dlrow a ni tsol s'eH .sselpleh s'eH
.senihcam yllat gnoma sucaba na
,sussateM yb ”feeB detlaS—
.saw eh erehw desilaer dna sgniraeb sih tog eh litnu
tehctah dlo eht htiw doow hguone stuc eh retfa kcab ti teg ylno ll'eH"
... saw thgir sih dna ,daeh sih gniwollip saw mra tfel siH
.noitcaer ym yb uoy deruonohsid I fi em evigroF"
,gnimaerd saw eh hguoht sa dekool eH
,edis eno ot daeh ,ylleb sih no llits saw eH
.depahs-ruatonim ylgnisserped
,railucep yrev lla saw tI
.mih fo tuo rits a kconk t'ndid dloc gnizeerf eht ni dekan tsomla gnieb taht deraeppa ti
maets fo sduolc yffup edam htaerb yM
"?uoy ekil ruatonim gnipparts gib a
.htuom eht ta gnimaof tsomla ,dnuora denrut eH
,remlac elttil a eb ot demees siroB
.tuo mih pleh dluoc I woh dna
tsniaga dleihs ylno eht saw sredle rieht rof evah sklof tcepser etanni eht enigami I .mih ta gniralg
,emit siht ta thgir daeh ym otni
.knurd erom dna erom tog llub eht sa
,siroB ,wonk uoY" dias I eciov duol-oot a nI
,tlep erab sih morf retaw dna wons eht egdolsid ot god gib taerg a ekil flesmih koohs ruatonim eht
,nwod skcab reven eh yaw eht ekil I
:eye s'dnim ym ni srehtaf dna srehtom eht lla ees dluoc I
.spot eht ta yawa deppihc yeht sa skaeb rieht gnitnulb snibor eht
,kcab sih no exa revlis sih dleh taht ssenrah kcalb eht dna
,noil eht mlac ot deganam ssel ro erom dah siroB emit siht yB
,dnuora gnikool ,derepsihw I ",setnorB"
hctid wollahs eht morf gnisir maets fo sduolc yffup deciton I litnu—ylevol saw tI
,wenk reve I sregit tsenif eht
.gnineve elbaicos a dneps ot erehwemos gnivah etaicerppa yllaer uoy ,sraey ni no gnitteg ,em ekil xof a roF
.doowylp fo teehs a htiw derevoc saw wodniw tnorf eht deciton I ,os did I sA
,ytiroirepus fo noisserpxe gums sih ta deyonna erom dna erom werg I sa deksa yllanif I ",oS"
,ylsuoituac neerG eht dessorc I
."selaT droW 563" meht gnillac
.em ta nwod neht dna ,nnI eht ot
... hu ... re ,hU"   .s'dlihc gnilbbab a ekil tuo emac eciov ym dna won mih fo deracs saw I .on ,yldaS
,etsat deriuqca na fo tib a si llub tew fo llems yrehtael mraw
... mih ta gnirats erew thguoht eh elpoep gnignellahc ylmodnar fo tibah lufwa siht dah eh dna
tnemom a rof dnuora dellor snioc revlis evif siH