.smra ynwarb rieht rednu dekcut yltaen
.rab eht dniheb saw siroB
eht gninwod saw setnorB ,elihwnaeM .em deyonna tahT
.ees uoy ,nnI eht ni slavirra wen htiw hcum xim t'nod I
.retaw ton si sihT"
— toof tes reve dah remotsuc on erehw
.sretnilps ot decuder saw flesti rood eht dna gnuws exa siH
,sserts fo semit ni yalpsid senipluv ew taht ecnaillirb eht htiW
.etisoppo eht etiuq saw tI
— dna esuoh eht fo ytilaiceps A
snroh sih fo eno no delapmi tog reniarts-puos A
.llub eht evres ot etsah sih ni flesmih dessip tsomla ,revres eht ,eno rehto ehT
.dias I "?em esucxE"
.snaem taht revetahw ,mih ot 'elbaruonoh' gnieb
.wonk t'nod I ,egatnavda lluf gnikat saw dna wenk eh ebyaM
,stroffe ym etipseD .gnikcohS
.uoy no kcirt a gniyalp era sraguoc eht"
,stnemmoc dessap dna delkcuhc
.retaw hserf fo draknat a
— gniht eno rof nnI egalliv ruo ni sraluger eht gnoma dezirp ylralucitrap saw
.gnidliub eht tfel dna sivlE na enod dah raeb eht
!eerf teg t'ndluoc eH
tbed ruoy ni ma I"
.trid saw I fi sa em ta dekool dna
ton s'tI .ti gniknird eb dluohs uoy kniht t'nod tub
.senob dlo ym morf taem eht ro
.stixe eht raen selbat ylniam
".ereht ,draknat ruoy ni retaw etsaw s'tahT"
sih fo egatnavda lluf koot nnI eht ni enoyreve ,yas ot sseldeeN
rof em ot yldneirf ylralucitrap dna
.nwod neteiuq ot mih ta deppans raguoc gnikool-ytfihs eht dna
).saw taht dab woh etar ot elbissopmi(
,ruatonim detlep kcalb gib eht ,dneirf ym woh fo elpmaxe cissalc a erahs ot em wolla
.pots t'ndluow llits eh dna
,lufetarg ma I nehT"
.rae derruf-kcalb s'ruatonim eht otni repsihw ot
,yllamrof dias eh
yawa devom dah I   .eno rab
?niaga trats dna pu teg tsuj ot gniog eh saW ?truh eh saW
.nni sih fo rood kcab eht ot pu gnilbma raeb ralop egral a fo erugif eht deips I wodniw kcab eht hguorhT
.delttes saw rettam eht litnu hcuop-yenom sih dna exa sih detacsifnoc raeb ralop ehT
.ti fo kniht I won ,rehtie hcnew modnar a htiw mih was reven I
,rednet lagel ylno eht saw siht ,ruatonim eht oT
.ereh stisiv ruoy yojne yllaer yeht — hu — ffats eht"
.nrut ni sdrawrof nael ot tsaeb taerg eht gnicrof
.emod sti tuo wolb ot tuoba saw onaclov depahs-ruatonim tnamrod eht desilaer ,yeht sloof on
.gniliec eht ta gnirats
.ssenprahs sti tuoba denrecnoc saw eh fi sa
,egdirf eht fo stnetnoc eht ot dessergorp dah sraguoc ehT
kaerb rood ssalg nwo rieht raeh t'ndid ,)ekatsim dab a(
,buc a saw I ecnis ereht raluger a neeb ev'I
.yaw taht tnasaelpnu ytterp eb nac eH
.esruoc eud ni tuo dnif dluow eH
.epip ym gnillifer ylision yb rethgual ym dih dna
.elixe na si eh eurt s'tI
.ksa ot eno eht eb ot gniog ton m'I taht wonk od I
,retnuoc eht ta detniop erew ,seye sih ekil ,snroh siH
.esle enoyreve dna rorret enivob eht neewteb ecnatsid sdray owt raelc a saw erehT
.ylwols yawa kcab ot detrats elpoeP
.esnes fo dioved saw I dna
.meht nesohc dah droldnal eht siroB yhw derednow netfo dna meht fo hcum kniht t'ndid I
,ecnis htiw klat ot reisae hcum neeb sah llub ehT
…   … exa prahs yllahtel dna ekil-namkrow
,seitilanosrep emas eht evah t'nod yeht tub
,t'ndluoc setnorB tub ,tas I erehw morf mih ees llits dluoc I
,nossetnorB setnorB ,ruatonim ehT
,nnI eht fo snortap ehT   .ylwols yrev
nehw elbat a deretsnom reven setnorB ,yllarutaN
.yllanoitasrevnoc ,deksa I
.wollaws eno ni diuqil eht fo flah denwod eH
rab eht ta esoht taht tcaf nwonk-llew a si ti sa ,yppah ton erew sraguoc ehT
,sruatonim fo selat raeh syawla uoy ,lla retfA
.raeb ralop hguot yllaer eno dna
,srekrow drah dna tneiciffe eb thgim yehT
— rab eht dniheb deklaw dna draknat eht detfil eH
.nruter ni hbraT eht morf tcepser gnigdurg steg eh eveileb I dna nossetnorB .rM morf kcits on sekat eH
,citehtap erom dna erom emaceb ti sa liated erom hcum uoy eraps lliw I
niaga elzzum ym denepo I
retaw sih deppus setnorB ,elihw eht llA
".ssendnik ruoy rof uoy knaht I dna
dna sdrawkcab yllacitsejam delias eH
,toof detekcub-nu sih htiw rettub eht no depmots
!uoy rof doog s'tI
:knird lausu sih dednamed dna rab eht ot revo edorts llub ehT
,fehc eht dna uoy fo tbed eht ni dna
'.ruatoniM .sv sraguoC' eb dluow ti ylekil naht erom dna
.nwot fo tuo morf sraguoc fo riap a erew yad taht rab gnidneT
.nwod toof sih tup eh emit hcae degnalc hcihw
.flesym tuoba no gnilbmar tsuj m'I dna setnorB tuoba uoy gnillet eb ot desoppus saw I
,erutan elbammalfni sih fo erawanu
fo draeh reven evah I"
.sgnideecorp eht hctaw ot em htiw rood eht ta deretsulc dna
dekluh hbraT eht dneirf ym
sdrawrof ylevarb denael neht
shgis ,strons fo surohc drazahpah A
,eye s'dnim ym ni saw aedi siht sa citnamor sA
noitome fo dioved saw eciov siH   ".tahW"
.yrots rehtona s'taht tub
,timda I ,tsrif tA
… hcaep a morf zzuf eht evahs dluow taht kool a em tohs ytfihS
,enilef lacipyt ruoy erew sraguoc ehT
.retnuoc rab nekao eht fo pot dehsilop eht gnitcesib edalb exa na fo pmowht duol eht yb dewollof saw noitseggus lufpleh siH
.tuo mih detoob yeht dna
,lassimsid rieht ni elor ym wonk t'nod yehT
.tsaeb eht gnisihpromoporhtna saw I ebyam ,niaga nehT
?mih ekil raguoc gnuoy enif a esuac em ekil xof dlo na nac mrah tahw ,lla retfA
,thgils deviecrep tseinit eht ta ecneffo ekat ot ytiliba etanni sih
.tlef elpoep woh tuoba tol a dlot moor eht ni esoht fo stnemegnarra gnitaes eht taht em kcurts ylneddus tI
,retaw eht ta deppis yletaciled
.sesaC sselepoH rof eno saw ti kniht I .reyarp kciuq rehtona tuo denaom I
,klaw ot llams oot saw I sa neve
"!od ylniatrec sremotsuc rehto eht wonk I
,paos fo draeh reve dah eh fi derednow I syad erew erehT
,yad yreve gnola em deggard dad yM
.selaT droW 563 sih si emaf ot mialc elos esohw
.seye rieht ni sraet
.kcab tnew reve eh fi detucexe eb dluow eh taht ecno em ot dessefnoc eH
.raor duol sih naht gnicanem erom neve saw eciov teiuq sih taht ynnuF   ".esaelp
,dnah gib sih ni ti koot llub ehT
.ecaf sih no kool desufnoc a ,deksa setnorB
,krims a edih ot epip ym no deffup dna ynnuf taht thguoht I ,trap ym roF
)ytfihS mih dellac I yhw wonk uoy won(
.exa egral yrev a dna repmet dab a htiw enoemos ot etilop eb ot syap tI
.lavorppa fo selbmum
.llub dnuob-elcsum eht naht ehtil erom raf
.noitasrevnoc fo muh eltneg eht dna
- etis eht sexif reve eh fi
— liomrut dna soahc yb dednuorrus era yeht erehw seirots
,drah dewollaws revreS !no og ,no og
,dna taorht sih deraelc setnorB litnu etulosba saw ecnelis gnitluser ehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
nehctik eht dnuora pal yrotciv a did sraguoc tnahpmuirt ehT
,ecalp eht fo ssenkrad teiuq eht deyojne I
.dnim s'ytfihS retne aedi eht was I raews I
.taht ta ti tfel dna flesym decudortni tsuj evah thgim I ,won wonk I tahw neht wenk I fI
,tsej ynnuf a saw tI
;emit eht fo tsom ,yllufesoprup
.knird a rof deksa niaga
.lortnoc ni erew sraguoc ehT
.rab eht ta llub kresreb eht fo yaw eht ni sniks rieht tup ot gnilliw saw eno-on ,yllauqe
.esruoc fo ,oot tnuoc snoisserpmi tsriF
.sraguoc eht no tceffe derised eht dah ti ,llitS
.daetsni sevlow emos ni derih siroB
.flesym deleets dna epip ym fo mets eht no dekcus I "?...era uoy dna"
.eerged tsehgih eht fo ecnasiun a emaceb eh no tnew emit sa ,revewoH
,pat eht morf draknat a dellif eH
draknat eht otni dereep eH
.yawrood eht ni gnidih llits ,emirc-ni-rentrap sih ta seye sih dekcilf eh sa hcton a deppils elims s'raguoc ehT
.reh wollof ot noos saw I fi gnirednow
.meht fo eno ton si )yldas( sihT
.yddot toh a revo retfaereht elat eht erahs ot erus eb ll'I dna — em wonk uoy
mih dekri taht esnopser ro noitca na dnif syawla dluow setnorB
detnurg ,deddon eH
.flesym ot noitnetta ward ot gnihsiw ton ,kcab denael I .os did eh sa
.meht dlot siroB tahw rettam on — nup eht esucxe
,tuo dehsols tekcub eht ni retaw ehT
.yawa devom ylkciuq ereht sklof rellams eht fo emoS
.knird retteb a uoy teg lliw I ,won emoC .suoires gnihtoN
,rood eht fo enap ssalg eht hguorht tuo delias ti drah os ti gnulf neht dna
.senilef eht ta flesmih dehcnual eH .tuo ton tub
.raguoc gnilbmert eht ot kcab denrut eh erofeb secaf napdaed 'senoyreve revo kool gnipeews a evag setnorB
,retnuoc eht fo edis raf eht morf siht lla gnihctaw saw I
.tuotS fo tnip ecin a tuoba woH"
shtaed 'sraguoc eht fo esuac eht eb dluow eugnot esool ym decnivnoc ylluf saw I
.retnuoc eht no draknat a decalp ylluferac
.foor eht flah tuo koot dna nwod ti deggut eH
,noisnet eht esae ot hgual elttil a htiw I dias ",lleW"
.selat erahs dna meht htiw tahc ll'I
ela derednulp fo sgek htiw etelper
.dednuos hgual elbatrofmocnu lanoisacco eht dna
.regnol on kcab flesym dloh dluoc I
— sregnarts etelpmoc erew yeht hguoht sa gnitca
.daed enots dellik tub ,niaga yawa deoohs ro yawa og ot deksa tsuj toN
"?gnorw sllems taht retaw tsuj ton si ti niatrec uoy erA .taht
.flesmih fo ssa etelpmoc a gnikam
,htrim ni dnuora gnillor ylteiuq saw ytfihS ,rood eht dniheB
ffo ekorb snoitasrevnoC
;emit eht fo emos ,yllatnedicca :sgniht ekorb eH
.elbmur suonimo na htiw gniliec eht koohs dna
",nossetnorB setnorB si eman yM"
.esuoh eht fo tuo teg ot esucxe na sa ylbaborp
.kresreb era yeht fi ylralucitrap
gnineppah saw tahw fo erawanu htob erew yeht os
pom eht ta ylirgna dellup eH
.llew sa tsuj saw tI
.nek sih dnoyeb saw ssenisub nwo sih dnim dna renroc a ni ylteiuq tis oT
.naem I tahw wonk uoy fi ,neppah ot neppah ot gniog saw revetahw
.tuo dnif reven yeht epoh I dna
.regnorts saw thgil eht erehw ,rood nehctik eht ot revo dna
.repmet htiw roolf eht ot tekcub pom desinavlag sih demmals eh sa
— si taht ,sraguoc eht — yeht os
.ffo yad sih morf emoh gninruter saw siroB
.deppots lla ti ,neht dnA
,su htiw eralg gnicanem lausu sih derahs dna rab eht otni yaw sih
,doots llub eht erehw ot tnew dna
,dna denruter eh sa revreS
.siht rof sraey fo elpuoc a kcab og ot evah uoY
htaerb sih fo gniffuh eht
.terger lla dluow ew
rewop dna egar ni dah ruatoniM eht tahW
.motsuc sih htiw desselb ton erew taht snrevat dna srab ybraen otni dna nnI eht morf yawa ssenisub evord eh ylniam tub
.nnI eht ni draeh saw sraguoc eht morf '!hal-puh' lanoisacco eht dna
.naem saw did sraguoc eht tahw tub
.snehctik eht pom ot esu yeht tekcub eht morf retaw etsaw eht s'tI
,sussateM yb ”nnI ehT tA“
.mih truh siht derugif I ,wohemoS
,em ot railimaf emoceb secaf nehW
,rab eht fo dne ym ot resolc devom
,elims ediw ylsuoicipsus a htiw
.yaw sih fo tuo tpek dna loots ym no tas
deffins ,ylluferac revo ti dekool
— morf semoc eh reverehw ro airuatoniM ni deneppah dab gnihtemos smees tI
sussateM yb ”nnI ehT tA“
.sraguoc yliw owt dna repmet nwo sih fo noitanibmoc a yb netaeb yldnuor gnieb saw ,pmurg dna elixe ,hbraT
egde eht kcehc neht
.owt ro hcton a nwod deppord gnihgual dna gniklat eht
,noitcurtsed dna soahc rof noitceliderp sih tuoba revetahW
.pollag 'setnorB dedne taht rettub fo kcolb dnuop-flah a saw ti dna dne na ot emoc sgniht doog llA
retsaf knird dna erom knird
.tcatnoc eye edam eno-on dna
".llems a si erehT
,nehctik eht otni tnew ,flesmih htiw desaelp yrev gnikool ,revres ehT
;elpoep deracs eh ;sthgif desuac eh
:dednetni eh tceffe eht dah eralg ehT
seitinutroppo erom niag
— shtreb refas dnuof yeht sa delwocs dna deffuh eH
.eman yb mih deteerg yeht hguoht neve
... retaw fo draknat a tnaw I ,dias I"
,ffo sdaeh rieht deraor ytfihS dna eh erehw
.slisnetu eht fo emos dleh taht emarf detnuom-gniliec eht ni
.tniop taht ta os ro shtnom xis rof nwot ni ylno saw eh kniht I
,ssenrah sih fo kcab eht morf exa sih llup d'eH
"?ti si ,setnorB"   .euqsurb os ,hO
.roolf tew eht dnuora ecar pacdam a nageb eerht lla dna snoitcerid tnereffid ni derettacs yehT
.etulas-flah a ni draknat eht gnisiar ,deilper eh
.deifirreT ?deracs I saW
mih htiw ekops eno-oN
rab niam eht ni elbat nedoow yvaeh a ffo sknuhc gnikconk ylippah tuoba tes dluow eh nehT
.snoitcurtsni sih eugaelloc sih evag eh ,yawynA
.pu meht tuhs ot hguone saw ecaf demarf-nroh gnidoorb ,krad sih morf kool elgnis a tub
.rood eht dniheb gninetsil ,thgir mih devres ti ,retcarahc yson A
— nwod saw setnorB rooP
,kcor a fo ecnagele dna ecarg eht htiw ,setnorB
.tellug sih nwod retaw naht rehto gnihtyna dah ,egdelwonk ym fo tseb eht ot ,reven ruatonim ralucitrap siht
.ria eht otni welf teef sih dna
setnorB dna staborca lanoisseforp ekil dekool sraguoc eht ,siht fo ruoh-retrauq a retfA
.em hsuh ot tuo dnah eguh a kcuts eH
.ria ni ekoms epip fo tnecs eht dna sllems suoiruc eht
knird rof tuo dewolleb hbraT ehT
.mih dniheb llaw noititrap nedoow eht otni demmals daeh sih litnu
krow eht did yeht ,llitS
.tuhs pay diputs ym tpek evah thgim I ,llits retteB
:yojne esaelP   .moc.sussatem
.desuac eh egamad eht lla rof tnemyap sa keew eritne na rof
.dne no doots tlep eritne siH
.selbat gnilttihw saw strops etiruovaf sih fo eno nehw ro
rof gnitiaw htiw flesym gnitnetnoc
.loof a fo tib a saw nossetnorB retsiM thguoht I
.on ,hsiffo-dnats gnieb ton s'tI
,selbat ta gnittis esoht naht
".htlaeh doog ruoY"
.mih llet ot stug eht dah reve eno-oN
.dleif a no erunam gnidaerps remraf a ekil
",dneirF"   .dehsuh saw I
— tuo skcen rieht kcits ot gniog t'nerew ffats eht ,nnI eht otni nopaew a gnirb t'nac uoy gniyas wal on htiw ,esruoc fO
.deeps dna ytilibixelf ni tsol eh
.nomel ton s'tahT
nossetnorB setnorB dneirf ym
"!motsuc ruoy etaicerppa ew ,haey — hhhu — ew esuaceb enola uoy rof ti detaerc fehc eht dna
"!nomel rettib s'ti — tI"
,depols sredluohs sih
dednettanu rab s'siroB gnivael erew dna )ekatsim esrow a(
;draknat ytpme eht ot welf yllaretil revreS   "!RRRAOM"
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,ecnayonna htiw trons mih gnikam
tsuj I os ,won era ew sa neht kcab esolc sa t'nerew I dna eH
.reward hsac s'siroB otni og ylthgir dluohs taht nioc ddo eht tekcop ot
.thgirf ni pmuj revreS gnikam dna ecafrus retwep eht gnitned
,revewoh yad ralucitrap siht nO
drah os ti devohs dna rood nehctik eht no dnah daorb sih decalp llub ehT
"— referp hcum ll'uoy erus m'I
.mih ta kool ot denrut moor eht ni sdaeh eht lla sa
.segnih sti ffo emac ti
.tnegreted fo wenk eh fi erus neve t'nsaw I
— )'ver rac' htiw semyhr ti( 'hbraT' eman eht yb kcap a sa evah yeht revetahw ro dreh sih ro ebirt sih sllac eh
siroB rof ruobal ot decrof saw setnorB
.gnorw ylsselepoh dna etanoitroporpsid yletelpmoc gnihtemos od ot ffo lerrab neht dluow dna
.kaerts ytsan live taht ro
,gnibbir derutan-doog dnim t'nod I dna sekoj lacitcarp dnim t'nod I
.won llew s'lla ,lleW
.yawrood eht ot nar I dna
,srekoolno eht fo esualppa eht ot
.yob ym ,knarp a ylerem saw tI !setnorB ?setnorB"
,yas ot desu rehtafdnarg ym sa gnignis nus eht dna gninihs sdrib eht htiw ,gnirps ylrae ni yad ralucitrap siht ,yawynA
.stirips ro reeb rof og t'ndid eh yhw dnatsrednu t'ndluoc I
,ruomuh fo kcal etelpmoc sih dna
.regnarts gninruter a htiw elat a derahs evah uoy ton ro rehtehw wonk reven uoy dna ,sgniog dna sgnimoc eht lla htiw ,rehtob eht htrow s'ti kniht t'nod yltsenoh I
.oga sraey ynam os
,wenk eh elpoep wef eht tsap depmots eh sa ylevissimsid delwocs eH
,mih dnuora sgnir nar yehT
.seye ruo ni rethgual fo sraet eht morf ees ylerab dluoc eW
dna sdon lanoisacco htiw 'nomel rettib'
.daor eht nwod sevil taht esroh gnuoy a fo daeh eht gnittih
.roolf eht ssorca yltnelis deddap dna ssenrah kcab sih morf exa sih dellup eh
.keew a rof kcab og t'ndid I
,tcejbo dluoc I erofeB
.doom eht nethgil ot dluoc I tahw did I ".knird
.llips eht pu depiw dna
.revo dna revo ssalg emas eht hsilop ylsseldne ot nageb dna ,ruatonim eht morf yawa
.klat ot deunitnoc I
.ereh steknirt sselhtrow erew yeht hguoht
.taebtraeh a ni dnim sih morf em dessimsid dna em was htob ytfihS
,edirp dna htgnerts suoivbo sih fo erutaerc a htiw eugra nac ohw teY
,ecneidua eht fo tser eht morf tnemesuma dna rethgual fo stooh eht ylnO
,pat retaw eht ot devom revreS sA
ecilam tsepeed fo eno saw kool siH .deralg dna
.sseccus tnerappa na knarp sih ,htuom sih ni wap
,drow hcae ni R eht gnillor
.liat ym gnilkcit meht leef dluoc I taht ni raf os swap kcab ym devohs dna
taes ym morf ylffits esor I
.doowerif ot decuder saw ti litnu
.was esle eno-on tahw was I sa
demriuqs dna delggurts eH .deirt eH
.emit a ynam ti was I — eil t'nod I
,elbat a ta gnittahc dna gnittis spuorg eht fo owt ro eno ta ylluftsiw gnikool mih thguac I eciwt ro ecno dna
.ytnuoc txen eht morf stac esoht daer dluoc I
nopaew eht fo edalb eht thguac eh exa lahtel sih htiw niawt ni revres eht reves ot detpmetta dna ni demrots setnorB nehW
.emaceb esahc nrobbuts sih denimreted erom eht dna emaceb setnorB reirgna eht
,eciov sih derewol eh ,yllairotaripsnoC
.setnorB fo ecnarelot yraw a depoleved a dah dna
.nioc eht ta gnitniop ,'?od I od tahw' ekil gnihtemos dehtuom dna eno ytfihs eht ta ylsselpleh dekool revres ehT
,tniop siht ta sih dah sa
.setnorB ,retaw ytrid s'tI"
,sussateM yb ”nnI ehT tA“
— dekcatta neht sraguoc ehT
"?tahW"   .pu dekool eH
,nialp a yrrac osla ot sneppah eh nehw yllaicepse
si yrots s’yadot dna
.llew sa tsuj saw hcihw
- dna ytiniffA ruF no yhpargotohp dna gnihtimsdrow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,ti debbarg setnorB sa
ylitfihs dnuora gnikool
.skrof dna sefink gnillaf morf deddorp gnitteg lluB diputs eht morf saw wolleb ehT
… eugnirem a ekil dekool
,detarbiv tsehc ym peed os lworg a ni dias eh
diputs ylurt gnihtemos did eh erofeb
"?nomel rettiB"   .revreS dias
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.renaelc muucav a dellavir taht htaerb fo gnikcus a htiw emit emas eht ta delahni lla eW
.setalp dna sdraknat
.daetsni sffutsdoof ot detroser dna worht ot stcejbo fo tuo nar sraguoc eht nehw yllaicepse
",yrdnus dna lla ot hsam niarg mraw sih dnemmocer dna
— dehgual EW erom eht ,yllautca — yeht erom ehT
,yawrood eht ot emoc ot mih ta dessih ytfihS
,eroferehT .seigolopa yM
.taf fo llab eht tog yeht erehw s'taht dna
.deneppah dah tahw desilaer dna
,em thguat rehtom raed ym taht daed eht rof reyarp elttil a eticer ot detrats I
,nehctik eht ni gnihgual llits sraguoc eht raeh dluoc I
nni egalliv eht fo droldnal eht si eh ,siroB rof sA
,yaw eht no saw gninokcer a derugif I
ta deralg setnorB   .llew os od senilef taht elims elttil live taht delims eh erofeb ,tnatsni na rof deppord waj s'revreS
.thgirpu niamer ot deganam ylsuolucarim dah taht loots a no dednal
,cra enif a ni sdrawkcab delppot ,setnorB dna loots eht
,yrev pu doots eH
etarg eht ni sgol fo gnilkcarc lacipyt erom eht decalper gniwolleb enivob dna
.moor kcots dna nehctik eht otni gnidael yawrood eht hguorht tnew eh erofeb ylnellus deddon ytfihS
,retnuoc eht no draknat eht deremmah eh
saw sihT.taht ssim I
:elffaw em ot netsil tuB
niaga draknat eht ta deffins ruatonim ehT
.thguard hcae retfa nwod draknat eht deknuht dna
".uoy rof doog yllaer
.mih ta dnah ot emac taht gnihtyreve gnissot elihw eht lla
snoitcuded tnaillirb ym fo niatrec saw I sa tsuJ
.revres eht ot nioc eznorb a dessap dna deddon
,deunitnoc eh ",haeY"
.gniees saw I tahw eveileb t'ndluoc I
,yletilop ylgnisirprus
.ecalp taht devol syawla evah I   .'tnelat'
.nwot ni tnew eh erehwyreve noisufnoc dna ecnayonna desuac snioc ngierof fo kcots s'hbraT ehT
.ti ni eciuj tiurf fo tnih a htiw retaw s'ti ,oN .oN"
yawrood eht tuo daeh sih kcuts ytfihS
.waffug ot ton gniyrt ,epip ym no dekohc ylraen I sa
,deppart saw eh dna dehcra saw kcab sih ,esroW
!llaw eht ni kcuts snroh sih tog llub etanutrofnu ehT
,sregnarts owt ro enO
.emit doog a gnivah
,stop htiw mih detlep yeht
rab eht otni derutnev sluos evarb wef A
.ffo tnew sthgil eht llA
,stnempmacne hguor rieht ot kcab gard ot sehcnew modnar gnibbarg ,egalliv a gnigallip
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rab eht ta flesmih tas setnorB
ylsuovren dehctaw dna retnuoc eht ssorca ti dehsup
.ees ot detcepxe I tahw ton saw was I tahW
,ssenilrus sih ,repmet-dab sih
".stnegreted gninaelc eht morf si llems nomel ehT
,yrgna naht esorom erom saw ecaf gnilwocs sih
mih ehtoos dna mlac ot semit lareves enevretni yllanosrep ot dah ev'I
slwoy raguoc fo dnuos ehT
,sdneirf fo gnag a htiw ereht gnittis saw eh dehsiw oot eh fi sa
,era yeht lufwa woh rettam on ,remotsuc a knarp reven dluohs uoy esuaceb sboj rieht tsol sraguoC ehT
,tahc yldneirf wols fo dnuos eltneg eht
;tnemmoc eht htiw eerga dluow rab eht ni nosrep eno toN
,tekcub pom eht otni toof thgir sih pmots ot deganam dah eh wohemos dna
,sessalg ,stekcub ,snap
,aitreni citamenic tsomla htiW
,ylsuovren gnihctiwt sreksihw ,revreS
— wap sih htiw revreS ta derutseg ytfihS
.pu dedne lla ti woh dna devaheb
— mih fo tuo ti yrp yllautneve ll'I
.regna desserppus ylerab htiw gnivaeh tsehc sih
.s'llub eht sa gniyrrow sa tsomla saw taht dnuos a
.neht kcab eman yb rehto hcae wonk t'ndid ew ,rebmemeR
.taht naht erom hcum em dlot ylerar s'eh