– evitisop yats ot tog I ,on ...fI
,reh fo tnorf ni gnileenk
– noitan eritne eht htiw rehtegot
,citats regnol on si evitarran ehT
.rehtegot swohs tsrif ruo ecnis tes loot ruo edargpu ot drah delggurts evah ew – erom yna toN
.snoitarbelec s’raeY weN eht fo trap egnarra pleh ot
– ytirepsorp rieht gnola gniworg
?uoy fo emas eht kniht I
,yletelpmoc ezorf I woh ylraelc rebmemer I
– srehto tsom syaw ni
,skrowerif raeY weN eht fo gninnigeb eht litnu niamer taht setunim wef tnacs eht nihtiw ssel hcuM
.noissimrep rof naht ssenevigrof rof ksa rehtar ll’I maerd ruo gnivas rof tub
.snoitciped  aroruA fo edam
– roma im ,gnidne reporp a yrots siht evig em teL
gnineve lla ytivitca htiw gniltsub neeb sah traeh neerg s’nattahnaM
,suovren eb ot nosaer doog yrev A
.dne ruo no raelc llA“
,slavitsef ytinummoc ,snoitarbelec loohcs fo strap dehpargoerohc ew dnuora nettog dah drow ecno neht
ecnednepednI fo noitaralceD ehT
?od ot detcartnoc neeb ev’ew tahw reviled tub od ot desoppus ew era esle tahW
,noitisop ni si mraws ehT
.mohtaf ot tluciffid dnif
”!oloX ,llac ruoY“
.su fo owt eht edisgnola werg tcejorp tra eht
enutrof nwo s’eno fo tcetihcra eht gnieb fo tcepsorp eht
...txen eht ot dworc eno morf srednaw ezag ym sa gnihtoN
.nwo sti no gaw ot gnitrats liat ym
:yromem evil ot noitidda ni latigid ot gnineppah eht timmoc ot
:ekats ta hcum s’erehT
;ylimaf ym htiw rehtegot ereht eb d’I
!erus rof s’taht ,ti esu t’nac I
.sthgin tsekrad eht gnitanimulli
;samenic ni ekil neercs gib elgnis a ton s’tI
”?oot ,esle lla ni rentrap ym eb ot tnaw uoy od
.wohs euqinu rehtar a emoceb sah
;sdnoces wef a rof tnelis sllaf riap ehT
trap llams a gnirahs
.serutcip htiw tub ,sdrow htiw ton reh llet lliw I dnA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
.htaerb reh hctac ot ytinutroppo eht sah yllanif ehs sa ecarbme ym otni gninael
.tops eht no seiriuqni rehtruf gnisserppus
– em rof enituor si noitseuq sihT
:sllet ti yrots esohw ytic eht sa tsuj
reh rof sgnileef eurt ym ssefnoc oT
:seirutnec eht tuohguorht srehto sseltnuoc ekil tsuj del
wonk rotcerid sti gnittel tuohtiw
;ytilaiceps s’aroruA era gnilletyrots dna trA
.krap eht evoba elcatceps eht ni tsol gnitteg si elcatceps eht ot noitidda ruo smees ti
rethguad reh segdelwonkca tibbar redlo eht litnu wap s’rehtom reh ta sgut ehs
– rof degnol ev’I gnihtemos seod ehs nehT
– nekorbnu si ebiv raeY weN eht
.em hsuhs ot tpmetta lufsseccus yrev a ni
.sraey eht hguorht yaw sti no
yletaidemmi dezilaer sah aroruA –
– speelS reveN tahT ytiC eht dnuora evitarran a
,detfig ,trams er’uoY“
.htiw nigeb ot boj ysae na t’nsi pu-
...gnineve s’yadot rof tpecnoc elohw ruo htiw gnola liaf lliw ssenisub ruO
sraey ;gnikam eht ni shtnom neeb sah wohs ruo rof snoitaraperp eht fo trap yM
– ssenisub ruo tratspmuj ot tcartnoc gib eno no gnihtyreve gniknab
,ekaseman ruoy ekil tsuj er’uoy em oT
tpecnoc ruo ,aedi ruo – nehw – fI
,yalpsid skrowerif eht yb deziremsem si enoyrevE
ylurt sruoy yb noitom otni tup sllits s’aroruA htiw detrats tahW
,sroloc tfos sreferp tra reH
ksa ot tuoba saw ylniatrec tsom ehs noitseuq eht ot rewsna eht fo yawaevig a neeb evah tsum elims daorb yM
.reh no pu kcehc ot erad yllanif I
”!evil gniog er’eW“
,snoitamrof ymene otni gnihsalc yrlavac
– tnedurp smees swap nwo ym otni sgniht gnikat erofeb ilajnA dna miJ gninraW
.sdrahcro dna sdleif ot yaw sevig ylwols alusninep eht fo ssenredliw eht sa ssap sedaceD
!yalpsid skrowerif eht gnitnemelppus wohs resal eht fo eton ekat ot smees ydobon
kraP lartneC evoba elgnatcer krad eht tniap segrahc s’krowerif eht erofeb taebtraeh a flaH
:ecnecsinimer ot emit emos ekat I oS
.yranoitats regnol on s’ti ,llew ...savnac ruo dna
.reh tem I yad eht ecnis dnim ym no neeb s'taht noitseuq eht ksa oT
”.enrobria meht teg s’tel
– dniheb tfel seitironim decalpsid dna denwosid eht
ytniatrecnu dna yteixna
dlroW dlO eht tfel evah ohw snezitiC
tnemom siht rof gnihsiw dna gnimaerdyad ,gninoisivne neeb evah I taht ton
sraef dna stbuod eht gnilleuq
.sredluohs reh no deirrac eb ot
,dluoc reve sdrow fo dnuos eht naht rehtraf hcum seirrac
desucof dna mlac niamer ot ytiliba ym ta yawa gnippihc
.ylf eht no ecnamrofrep a fo wolf eht gnitsujda dna
.noitamalcca citsaisuhtne rieht yb devom ylpeed
.thgindim ot sdnoces ytrihT ”.siht
...su eciton ot sklof teg ot gnihtemos eb tsum erehT
– sgnidliub fo sedis eht ro neercs no detcejorp
elzzum ym fo tnorf eht dehcuot regniferof reh litnu ton
...uoY .cigam ...saw tI
scinahcem dna scinortcele fo noitcelloc dezis-xob azzip a hcae ,senord 002 fo erac gnikat – stirpluc eht tuo stniop
– efil ot semoc eceiprae ym sa eirever ym fo tuo em sekahs eciov s’ilajnA fo dnuos neddus ehT
thgil ni detniap
oc dna eugaelloc ruoy tsuj naht erom eb ot stnaw ehs fi
!meht no pu evig t’noD
...ew tnemom eht lleps ruoy rednu meht dah uoY
snepeed ssik eht sa kcab gninaeL
!sdworc eht detavitpac evah ew
gnihctiwt sreksihw dna gnipoord srae ;serutaef reh otni dehcte
.ssap sedaced eht sa degaw si raw dna spoleved edart
,tuoba serac ydobon dren yhs eht ,em htiw dnuora kcuts ev’uoy dnA .lufituaeb ...ynnuf
aroruA nwonk ev’I sraey eht lla retfa neve
.seniltuo eltbus
.sehctaw ytiC kroY weN sa neve sdrow rof gnilggurts si trapretnuoc laer sih
.ti no slausiv tup ew woh dna – yrots siht llet ot nesohc ev’uoy yaw ehT
– tcejorp noitamina elpmis a saw tI
,thgindim ta yltcaxe evitarran s’wohs ruo fo esruoc eht retla ot noissimrep rof tneilc ruo ksa erad t’ndid I
?od ew dluohs tahw
.og-on era 371 dna 67 ,81“
– su rof tneve siht no gnidir si tol A
:s’og nwo rieht ni oidar yeht sa efil ot semoc
.yllacov etacinummoc ot ytiliba eht fo reh gnivirped tcefed citeneg erar a
;snoitarbelec ylimaf ta ralupop emaceb tsrif stca ruO
”.rehgih su gnikat m’I
,gnimochtrof era snoissecnoc on sA
,dlroW weN eht ot yawetag eht gnimoceb
savnac ruo noitnem ot toN
.smaerts evil dna VT tnuoc uoy fi erom snoillim yllaitnetop dna – srotatceps dnasuoht derdnuh a tuoba t’nerew ereht tub
.hcnual ot ydaer dengis dna
.rehtegot dednetta ew sessalc owt morf yb gnissap ni dna eman yb ylno em gniwonk
yrotsih – s’noitan eht
.dah reve ev’I eno diviv tsom eht si ti neht ,maerd a si siht fI
”!gnimaerd ton er’uoy taht foorp deen uoy esoppus I siht ekil dewaj-kcals ereht gnidnats uoy htiw
,yad eht ot tsomla sraey neetruoF
”?enim od uoy sa hcum sa
.speels ydobon erehw ytic eht osla si speels reven taht ytic eht nehw
raw a ,noitan a fo htrib ydoolb eht hctaw yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
– krow ruo deviecer sah ecneidua eht woh flesreh yb tuo kcehc nac ehs erofeb neve
:noziroh eht no raeppa kcaJ noinU eht gniylf setagirf yad eno litnu
...nees ton er’uoy fi ssenisub on si ssenisub wohS
.gnihtyna egnahc
.trohs gnillaf era snoitatcepxe ruo ekil hcum yrev skool ti fi neve cinap etunim-tsal fo dnik yna rof esu on evah ew tub ,rettahc eht wollof ot elbanu si aroruA
dda ehs dluow esle yhw – evah tsum ehS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,reve sa lufitud ,miJ
...gnimaerd ma I sselnu ...sselnU
ecnamrofrep ruo ot dda ot ekil d’I tahw denialpxe I sa tub
:syalpsid sutats ym kcehc I
,latot ni sneercs rellams hcum derdnuh owt fo desopmoc s’ti
!deedni ti kaerb ro ti ekam
.smrof retnec sti ta kroY weN htiw draobaes nretsae eht no tleb natiloportem eht elihw
detaerc sah agima enilef yM
mraws enord ruo fo lortnoc ekat ot pu-sdaeh trohs a ilajnA gnivig m’I
leef I ssensseltser eht tcerider ot erehwemos
,spag elbaeciton gniwohs savnac gniylf ruo tuohtiw gniliaf senord net ot pu etarelot dluoc I
,efil ot emoc srotcejorp resal ruO
,yltnatsni tsomla sa stpure esualppa
!elbisiv si krow ruoy erus ekam ot dah I
.reporp krap eht fo weiv retteb a teg ot tnempiuqe ruo gnisuoh kcahs elttil eht morf yawa reh gnidiug yltneg ,og tel I os
,yletal gnipeels elbuort dah ev’I
.ecneidua eht fo noitanigami eht htiw gnicnad savnac delit a no
– seitrebil citsitra emos nekat evah yam I“
.netfo os desraeher dah I snoitanalpxe eht deremmats I sa seye eht ni reh kool ot derad yldrah I reh ot derapmoc ysmulc os tlef rehtegot delbboc dah I tahw
!htiw nigeb ot neeb ev’I naht reipmuj neve em ekam ot devres ylno taht ,esruoc fO
.ti dlareh pleh ot ereh era em dna aroruA
.egaugnal ngis derutseg ot troser ot deen I
.oloX ,uoy ot sknaht ylnO“
– emitefil a fo tcartnoc eht gnidnaL
,detcurtsnoc si trof A
– rentrap ssenisub ym naht erom eb ot tnaw uoy od ,aroruA
?gnihtyna rof reh ta dam eb I dluoc woH
t’ndluoc I erom semit derdnuh a skcehc thgilf-erp ym revo og dluow I fi nevE
,egassem eht yevnoc ot swap reh deen t’nseod ehS
– wohs ruo fo trap lacinhcet eht fo egrahc ni eno eht ytip d’I
!omlo la sarep ridep nedeup es oN
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,sdraobyrots s’aroruA nees ev’I
.etasnepmoc lliw smhtirogla lortnoc ehT“ ”?melborP
...tey dna ,rodirroc thgilf ruo htiw devorppa ev’ew tahw htiw
...rehtegot loohcs hgih detrats ew nehw kcab
yrotsih s’kroY weN fo snwod dna spu htiw gnola og
.etad ot noissimmoc suoigitserp tsom ,tsegral ruO
.noitanimulli mumitpo secaf selgna gniweiv fo egnar egral a taht os thgir dna tfel etator yllacidoirep ot mraws eht tcurtsni ll’I
.segarrab yldaed gnihsaelnu snonnac
:eludehcs raluger eht fo trap t’nsi siht taht
.retpocdauq a yb deirrac hcae
?dluow ew depoh ew sa won dna ereh sessam eht niatretne ot liaf ew fI
.tuptuo noitcejorp rieht fo stimil eht ot srotcejorp resal eht pu knarc dna maerts oediv eht otni mhtirogla gniretlif ruotnoc elpmis a dda I oS
.swap s’aroruA ni seil won gniliaf ro gnideeccus
.gnikaerb fo tniop eht ot
.smelborp derutcurts dna smhtirogla htiw doog etiuq m’I
– su egagne ot slaiciffo s’ytic eht ecnivnoc ot eno eht neeb sah aroruA ,dlot eb hturt
:serutcip fo ecnad laitselec eht yb detavitpac seno ylno eht ton era
,demrala eb t’noD“
.otni skrow reh nrut ew seirots detamina eht dna tra ekil-efil s’aroruA ”tsuj“ ton s’tI
.noituac fo edis eht no rre ot retteb s’ti tub
;ecnamrofrep ruo detartsehcro ehs elihw aroruA detpurretni t’nevah I
:ybboh derahs a otni denrut tcejorp ssalc tra ehT
,dneirf tseb ym ...aroruA
– luftuons a si eltniucztioloX
ruo setaba skrowerif eht fo ytisnetni eht sA
.won semit derdnuh a stsilkcehc ym revo enog evah tsum I
.latipac sti gnimoceb si madretsmA weN
:noisseforp a otni
.reh ot raed dna raen esoht rof devreser eno
;swap ym esu ot deen I reh ot tsartnoc nI
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
releeH eulB eht eiuolB yb ”silaeroB aroruA“
?”odaisamed oreiuq et“
;ti rof erutseg laiceps a detpoda neve ehs ;em rof emankcin reh ...oloX
hsiulb//:sptth no seirots fo noitcelloc gnidnapxe ylwols sih dnif nac uoY
;eninac a sa od I naht ssenevisserpxe labrev-non fo eriotreper retaerg hcum a sah ehs enilef a sa
.ti ot detcaer sklof woh dnA
?gnihctaw enoyna t’nsi yhW
meht llet ot sdrow thgir eht dnif oT
trapretnuoc eganam dluoc I sa doog sa reh savnac eht no pU
,efil retteb a rof hcraes ni
.tnemegaruocne ro ecnarussaer
,tuons ym fo edis eht sesserac swap reh fo eno
eueuq kcabyalp eht ot eltit dne terces eht dda I – em nodnaba ot ecnahc a sah ecnedifnoc erofeb dna – traeh gnikaT
,krow drah fo tol a
ytic evitan ruo fo yrots eht dna
,noissimretni tuohtiw seunitnoc ecnamrofrep
?mh ,seitrebil citsitrA“
:srednatsyb eht ot raelc ytterp si noitautis eht
,latot ni setunim net tuoba koot wohs ehT
,sgnileef ym ssefnoc ot ecnahc eht evah I erofeb esirprus eht tuo gnirugif reh naht flesym fo loof a gnikam em retteB
.draobyrots s’aroruA ot
– aedi eht ekil I ?siht tub
.noitcerid ruo ni ecaf ot setator won putes noitcejorp gniylf ruo ,daehrevO
.redluohs ym no hcuot tfos a ...s’ereht nehT
”!xelA ,ereh og ot ydaer er’eW“
,ees I lla tnemom yrev siht ni tub
)eb dluohs ti sa ro( saw ti sa dlrow eht erutcip ot noitanigami reh depleh sah gniraeh dna eciov fo ecnesba ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.raey eht fo nrut eht revo enilyks eht etanimulli lliw taht skrowerif eht htiw detrecnoc
...reh ot esolc em gnillup
,daeh ym fo kcab eht gnitroppus wap enO
,noitanigami fo hcterts yna yb kcirevam a ton m’I
oga gnol oot ton noitcif fo edis yzzuf eht derevocsid ohw retirw tsiybboh
.etis hcnual ruo morf og rieht em gnivig egakoT miJ dna ehs
reh ot sgnileef eurt ym ssefnoc ot gniyrt fo gnikniht neve dnA
– reppac tsal sti rof niaga ytisnetni ni pu gnikcip skrowerif eht gniciton
raey dlo eht htiw rehtegot sdne nwodtnuoc eht sA
,sthguoht gnicar ym ni gningier – hcuot tfos reH
– lennahc derahs ruo no eciov s’miJ
fo sllac lufreehc yb deinapmocca
:sraey eht revo devlove evah sdohtem ruO
...ecneidua eht yb dedeeh t’nera
.meht ot od thgim tnaryt a gnihtyna naht regnorts
,esimorp eht – maerD naciremA ehT
snezitic sih ot noitatneserper etauqeda gnitnarg tuohtiw stifeneb eht paer yawa dlrow a flah gnik a dluohs yhW
...ot egaruoc eht dnuof reven tsuj ...ev’I
tub – em ot ylno ton ,gnilaeppa os ti sekam tahw s’tI
”!otag ,krap eht pu til uoY“
yrots a htiw scinhcetoryp dnuob-yks eht tnemelpmoc ew dna
.eveihca yllautca ew tahw ot pu sevil yldrah mret lacinhcet eht
dworc eht gnivresbo enoemos fo sdnoces ytriht fo pilc nupsemoh a tub wohs ot gnihtoN
.tniop eht ot erom si laciretsyH
noitamalcxe elgnis eno otni yawa gnidaf
.eergidep ym gninetrohs rof reh ta dam eb I dluoc woh
,dniw eht ni gniyaws seert dna ssarg ees nac I raews I
,siht uoy llet ot woh gnol os derednop I
noisnapxe dnuobtsew dipar a leuf ot stnargimmi fo snoillim gnitcartta
;noitarran eht gniyalrednu kcart oidua on si erehT
.yrrufos.okceg-
...saw ti fi ro erutseg yldneirf a tsuj saw ti fi aedi on evah I
,won dlrow nwo reh ni degrembus ylpeed si aroruA
”?eivom a morf tnereffid od uoy tahw si woH“
stsilaiceps er’eW
.emit tsrif eht rof deklat ew ecnis lleps ruoy rednu em dah uoy ekil tsuJ“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
– emit tsrif eht rof em gniees fi sa
.evoba skrowerif eht fo stsrub eht neve
,drawyks gnikool erah gnuoy a tops I litnU
?ynitsed rieht fo sretsam eht eb ot ytinutroppo eht
rieht ,seciov rieht fo sdnuos eht rof gnihcraes srae ym gnileviws flesym hctac llits I semitemoS
,serohs sti tsniaga pu gnihsaw sevaw s’citnaltA eht
setunim neetfif otni desnednoc
:seirots reh fo woh dna tahw eht yevnoc ot dnuos deen dluow aroruA taht toN
sihT”!raeY weN yppaH“
– em rof elbattegrofnu
,demrof si dnalrehteN weN fo ynoloc hctuD eht nehT
,nwot gninoegrub eht fo ngierevos eht emoceb hsitirB ehT
.segaugnal tnereffid nezod a ni
revoc ylbisaef nac ew sa kraP lartneC fo hcum sa morf elbisiv s’ti taht os ylluferac savnac gniylf ruo fo noitisop eht nesohc ev’eW
emitefil a fo ecnahc ruo ,doG em pleh os tub ,)noitatneserp eht htiw seitrebil emos ekat dna(
,sexaler ylbaeciton ehs rof
?iS yas tsuj ehs did
.niatrec rof si taht
,rehtruf sdlofnu yrots eht sa og dna emoc spihs eroM
.seitiliba gniward detimil ym fo tseb eht ot airetefac a ekil kool edam I tahw ni
;gnikil reh ot spilc trohs fo noitcelloc eritne na egnarraer ot aroruA rof ppa draobyrots a pu tes ev’I :eno rof
!nwod gniog si lasoporp A
,staebtraeh wef a rof em sdrager ehS
:eve s’raeY weN siht no skrowerif laer eht fo noisrev detamina na eb lliw wohs ruo fo ecneuqes lanif ehT .aroruA ot
...ynapmoc a dnuof ot em htiw pu derentrap
– seye nwo reh htiw noitcaer s’ecneidua ruo gnissentiw morf reh peek t’nac I
.gniwohs yb tseb skrow gniod yllautca er’ew tahw gnillet
.neht ecnis rehtegot kcuts ev’ew dna
”?ssalc tra ni tcejorp a rof uoy nioj ot ekil d’I fi em ksa ot tsuj siht lla deraperp yllaer uoY
og eht no snrettap thgilf s’mraws ruo tsujda ot evah ll’I
,trats eht ta toh os od t’ndid ew dezilaer I nehw ylf eht no tpircs ym gniludehcser ysub neeb evah yam I
.ti htiw gnola tsaoC tsaE naciremA eht dna
– yrots ruo yb dnuoblleps
.nalp thgilf laiciffo eht morf noissergid elttil ruoy ssim t’ndid I neve tub
elat reH :aroruA rof hcaer fo tuo era ecnelis dna dnuos fi nevE
ynapmoc dna pihsdneirf ruoy eulav I tahT
ecneidua eht fo doom eht gnidaer ta gnihsinotsa si ehs
egaugnal ngis sesu egnahcxe ruo fi neve
savnac gnirevoh a otno detcejorp serutciP
serutcip diviv reH .skrow reh dna
”!wohs thgil eht detsoob uoy woh roN
!ordnajelA ,ynnuf er’uoY“
ytilauqe dna ecitsuj ni feileb eht
erif dna thgil fo nrettap tnaillirb a ni
.si taht ,em t’nsaw ti fi
.ilajnA dna miJ :werc hcet ruo pleh ti dluow rehtien dna
dezilaer t’ndah I esruoc fO
?enola su fo owt eht tsuj s’ti nehw
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,swap reh ni yalc ma I
– raey wen eht etarbelec ot ereh ton m’I raey siht tub
noziroh tnatsid eht no sraeppa lessev gnilias a sA
,reh dehcaorppa tsrif I nehw lacitpecs saw ehs llet dluoc I
.edalg lanoisacco eht yb decalper eb ot gnidecer ylno
don esret ym hctac ot reh fo tnorf ni spotpal fo riap eht gnivael ylno ezag reh
.silaeroB aroruA eht
.ecnereffid yna sekam krow utpmorpmi ym fi ees ot dnuora gnikool ,niaga pu teg I
”?gnorw gnihtemos od I diD“
.nwot llams a otni sworg tnemelttes eht
– oloX ,era uoY“ ”?on ,thgir ma I
.kcerw niart a ,on – retsasid a m’I
:reh tem ev’I ecnis tnuoc ot tfel stigid wap on evah I raey rehtonA
.seno ylno eht ton raf yb
.wonk uoy ,’olleh’ gniyas tsuj ...ekiL
;thgilf ekat ot sretpocdauq eht llet I tigid xedni ym fo hcuot a htiW
– tnemraedne llams reH
!srettam lanosrep ot semoc ti nehw ssem ypmuj a hcus t’nsaw I taht tnemom yrev siht ni hsiw I woH
noitanitsed eht neeb sah kraP lartneC rebmemer nac I ecnis raey yreve ekil tsuJ
.dne na ot semoc noitarran eht erofeb
.nigeb nac wohs eht
.em htiw secrof gninioj eerga ot hguone reh gnisserpmi fo epoh eht ni
.raen sward noisulcnoc a
.aera rediw a ot elbisiv yalpsid s’aroruA ekam ot si ssenisub fo redro tsrif eht
...era uoy laiceps woh aedi on evah uoy ,aroruA
”!nosaer a rof enoz ylf-on a dellac s’tI
”!agima ,sruoy si egats ehT !neiB¡“
.nottub trats eht spat wap reh
sthgil tnaidar eht – silaeroB aroruA eht
segami eht fo seniltuo eht tsoob etihw dna der ,eulb tnarbiV
– foereht kcal dna – tnemhsinotsa dna yoj fo stuohS
”.seiks eht decreip ew
.dnuos fo ecruos rehto yna tuo nword ecneidua eht dna scinhcetoryp eht
...ti htiw hguorht og ot em si sekat won ti lla
,regnuh morf hsirep sknar rieht tsgnoma sdnasuoht dna snrub dnalemoh rieht sa nevE
:maerD naciremA eht fo edis krad eht ot semoc ti nehw kcab dloh t’nseod ehS
.tnatsni na stsal taht ytinrete na
.rehto hcae ot gniklat meht raeh
– ksa reven d’uoy diarfa saw I !is ,oloX ,iS“
gnileef neeb evah tsum ehs erusserp eht
.tseuqer ym fo troppus lluf ni meht dnif ot denetraeh saw I
gniggeb ylbakatsimnu
:aroruA rof elggurts cinatit a neeb evah tsum ti taht suoivbo s’ti tub
:uoy ni ees I tahw dnatsrednu uoy tel ot woh
yllautcA ”.enif er’eW
:gniylf fo gnikaepS
.evloser ym no gniggan
.noitisoppo nepo neht
.serutcip gnivom htiw gnilletyrotS
.egA lairtsudnI eht otni
,enips ym nwod dna pu revihs a gnidnes hcuot reh
– retal edutitarg ruo gniwohs fo sdnuor wef A
,etum-faed nrob saw ehS
”?edis ruoy no raelc llA
!esle gnihtyna naht erom ytisonimul eriuqer eW
.txen od d’ehs tahw ot sa niatrecnu
gniyrc rieht ,rethgual
m’I – nekopsnu sniamer noitseuq sihT
;gnireenigne thgil rof
.enif eb ll’ew ;hsittiks os eb t’nod ,oloX“
– sneercs-inim fo dnuopmoc gniylf ruo pu gnithgil dna gnidnif thgil detaludom rieht
.ti dnuora lla yalpsid skrowerif laer eht fo noisrev dezilyts a gniwohs yltnerruc
nigeb ot tuoba txen eht dna dne ot tuoba raey rehtona htiW
dah I aedi eht reh wohs ot
no dekrow ylgnikatsniap
raeY weN yppaH a rof sehsiw tseb htiw gnola derahs era sessik dna sekahs wap ,secarbmE
– em ot KO reh sngis aroruA
.em ot lla fo tsom
.raey eht fo nrut eht htiw cnys ni etanoted ot dnuob sehcnual sllehs lairea fo evaw tsrif ehT
.ereh redro ni s’gnihtyreve ...xelA“
tserof dexim ni derevoc flesti alusninep eht
:snoisivne ehs mrof yna ekat ot ydaer
?erus uoy era ,xelA“
.  serneg ynam ni delbbad sah dna
– yrutnec ht91 eht sretne kroY weN eht tniop eht yB
!kaerb ton dna ekam s’ti deredisnoc sgniht llA
.gnizama s’ti – od uoy tahw ,era uoy ohW .uoy llet ot
:stsefinam sraey derdnuh ruof naht erom saw ti sa nattahnaM
.ylpmoc ot gniliaf eerht swohs ylno neercs sutats ym
.odinác ,noitnetta s’enoemos teg ot syaw relpmis s’erehT“
:krow drah fo htrow sraey dna – ynapmoc ruo fo etaf eht htiw reh tsurt ot diarfa ton m’I dnA
.klat ot eerf swap ruo evah yllanif ew
nworf lufworros a
– epaneL eht yb detibahni
...noitisop ni si savnac ehT
,sdnasuoht net gnisuoh ytic elbatirev a ot nwot a morf gniworg
,modeerf rof hsiw eht
”!ni m’I :oS .tcaf ni ,tol a
:nalp tnereffid a htiw pu emoc ev’I oS
aroruA – wap thgir ym gnivaW
,detsuahxe skool ehS
reilrae lrig gnizama siht ksa ton uoy did thgir dna tsuj si taht lla fo eman eht ni woH
– s’ytic eht fo tnemom gninifed A
.dnuorg evoba teef 002 thgieh gnitarepo tes-erp sti ot dednecsa gnivah
.lufsseccus neeb syawla t’nevah I tub ,maet eht fo tser eht tespu ton ot dluoc I tseb kcerw suovren a gnieb edih ot deirt ev’I
:reh wenk I sa gnol sa rof – fo tmaerd
.draobyrots s’aroruA otni hctap I snoitcurtsni wen ym ot stpada dna sdnecsa mraws eht sA
eson ym fo niks kcalb-laoc eht erehw thgir ,tuons ym fo egdirb eht no sessik fo tsetfos eht tnalp spil reH
.rodirroc thgilf ruo ssergsnart ot desoppus ton er’eW
?uoy fo emas eht kniht I esuaceb tsuj dnuora kcuts I taht dnim ruoy ssorc reve ti diD
”.tsael ta ,emit siht
nioj ot etatiseh t’nod ohw srotatceps suoiruc erom stcartta eltsub dna eltsuh ehT !erocne ,erocnE
;edutitpa nwo reh ot derapmoc reffo ot elttil os dah I taht diarfa os saw I
– ot tnaw reve I dluoc woh
.sdneirf ruo ,seilimaf ruo
.skrowerif eve s’raeY weN eht hctaw ot gnirehtag
?enoemos ot sgnileef ym ssefnoc ot egaruoc eht retsum ot semoc ti nehw tuB
.neht ma I tahw ylreporp ebircsed t’nseod suovreN
!eciton sekat eno on llits dnA
!draobyek eht fo tnorf ni moor ekam ot desoppus tsuj saw I
;tem reve ev’I tsitra detfig tsom eht si ehS
:rettops ym eb lliw miJ elihw
.ysatnaf dna ytilaer neewteb dnelb ylsselmaes wohemos yeht
,sesae yllanif shtnom tsal eht fo ytniatrecnu dna noisnet ehT
– evila emoc serutcip eht skrow reh revo rednaw ezag ruoy tel uoy nehW
,srotcejorp owt ruo fo egnar ni senord eht gnipeek elihw ,txeN
:roloc fo smossolb tnaidar yb pu til yks a otni
bal retupmoc eht ot em ynapmocca ot reh ecnivnoc wohemos dluoc I litnu os deniamer ehS
?gnihton fo tuo efil wen a tliub evah ohw
:reh ot kcab ngis I .t’ndluoc I
:raf yb eno ylno eht ton tub
ecaf reh gninroda selims teews reh fo eno htiW
;evitarran eht otni deppils dah ecneirepxe lanosrep hcum woh
– elims eniuneg a ni pu til ecaf reh litnu saw tahT
srotatceps fo sdnasuoht ynam fo
savnac enrobria ruo sdrawot detcerid era saremac dna senohp fo sedutitluM
:ecarbme s’aroruA ot dleiy I sa seciov ynam fo
– pu thgil lliw su evoba seiks eht litnu tfel setunim owT
,eniuneg si krims reh
,kcab rewol ym no gnihsup rehto eht
,emuser s’!hA dna s’!hO rieht neht
wohs ylnevaeh eht ot noitnetta lluf rieht nrut srotatceps erom dna erom
:dnuora kool ot pu teg I noitnetta s’aroruA ward ot ton erac gnikaT
...miJ ,ilajnA ,KO“
rehto yna ekil raey a saw ti fI
– tneserp eht dehcaer tsomla sah evitarran ruO
!cigam demrofrep uoy
.erom yna skrowerif eht ta detcerid ton ylno
,noitazilivic nretseW yb dehcuotnu ssenredliw A
.gnipyt ot trever ot dah ehs os ,neht kcab egaugnal ngis ni flesym etalucitra ot woh wonk t’ndid I
– hsiruolf ot seunitnoc ynoloc eht savnac eht nO
– noisserpxe delzzup a htiw em gnihctaw
.yaw euqinu ,nwo sti ni ti dloheb ohw lla gnivom
deen I nehw swonk syawla ehs yaw emoS
edisa eceiprae ym ssot I erofeB
– od seivom tahw s’taht
:sdrow fo ecneuqes a hguorht secnad yldiulf wap rehto reH
,thgin retniw kroY weN raelc a fo sroloc tevlev eht yb demarf
kcab gniyalp strats pilc edam-fles ym seod ti sA
– stneve ria-nepo llams
”!enO .owT .eerhT .ruoF“
;gnitsej s’ehs ezilaer ot tnemom a em sekat ti kramer tsal reh no krep srae ym sA
.lenap yrots eht no desucof ylelos noitnetta reh
sdaeh a tuohtiw nwod gnikaerb sevol taht
.thgindim ta wohs cinhcetoryp eht hctaw ot tops a rof gnikool sdneirf dna seilimaf htiw
– reh edisgnola gnikrow dna gniwonk fo sraey retfa em neve gnidulcni
.saw noitautis nwo reh suoiracerp woh no gnittel tuohtiw em si taht sevren fo gab eht erussaer ot ygrene eht dah ehs llits dna
,yllaretil dna ylevitarugiF
:levoN .wena dlot si
:yojne esaelP   .moc.yrrufos.okceg-
,rehto hcae sdrawot gnihcram snoilattaB
ssenisub ruo ees ot ecnahc elbaiv a evah ew wohs siht retfA
su dnuora dlrow ehT
:gnineve siht fo tneve gnikcar-evren tsom eht ti htiw dna
,sdnuos rehto lla tuo nword stuons dna selzzum dnasuoht derdnuh a morf noitalibuj dna sreehc
smaet skrowerif eht htiw erahs ew lennahc oidar ehT ”...eviF .xiS .neveS“
.pot eht ot ti ekam nac ew tneilc ruo desimorp ew tahw reviled ew nehw
setunim fo rettam a ni yb ssap sedaced sA
.xelA ,siht rof uoy knahT“
...ot mih wolla seitiliba egaugnal gningis sih sa tsaf sa gningis swap sih
.ecnamrofrep nwo ruoy fo erom nees evah dluoc uoy hsiw I ...uoy – aroruA“
”!rebmemer ot wohs a ytic eht evig s’teL .enif eb ll’uoY
.ssik etanoissap a ni enim nioj spil reh sa niaga esnes gnikam strats gnihtyreve
:efil ym fo tser eht rof ti terger ll’I ro ,won uoy ksa ot deen I
.ruf fo segitsev tsrif eht ot yaw sevig
;tca s’eve eht fo trap er’ew taht dezilaer evah tsum srotatceps fo puorg tsesolc ehT
dna yoj fo ecnad dnuor lufroloc a otni tsrub dlrow renni ym sees – erom
,releeH eulB eht eiuolB yb ”silaeroB aroruA“ saw
,htiw tuo detrats ew seno DCL eht decalper evah srotcejorp resal fo riap A
:ylf ot denrael sah tI
:ytilaer fo selbuort eht yb eb yam smaerd ruoy nekorb dna derettab woh rettam on dna
;skrowerif eht fo sesion eht rof tub tnelis nellaf sah
ecneuqes a sdda taht pilc edam-fles trohs a si noitubirtnoc yM
– rehtegot su fo owt eht thguorb tahw osla era
,yoj sseldnuob ym fo
– ees ot enoyreve rof reh llet lliw I
,srerimda ruo ot wob ew wap ni waP .ni
.rewop ot esir s’noitan ruo fo ekaw eht ni
.guh thgit a ni flesreh sdnif ehs
,noitasrevnoc fo stib tsrif ruO
– erahs I dna aroruA eno – maerd enO
stnediser sti fo ecnedifnoc eht
– yoj fo raet lanoisacco eht neve ,selims eltbus
– kroY weN sdael maets fo taebtraeh A
...era sgniward reh
.yb kcit raey dlo eht fo sdnoces tsal eht sa gnitnahc strats dworc delbmessa ehT ”...thgiE .eniN .neT“
– did ew woh ksa nac ehs erofeB
ssalc tra na sa detrats tahw nrut ot su wolla dluow taht shtap dekcip su fo htob sreerac ruo no ediced ot emit saw ti nehw dna
.noitautis tnereffid a si won
.gnikcilf srae ,gnihsiws liat
,neht ecnis hcum os hguorht enog ev’ew
.kcatta cinap a emoceb ot ecnahc a sah neve ti erofeb
,tib a slliks laicos dna gniward ruoy no krow ot deen ll’uoY
...dnapxe ot seunitnoc tnemelttes eht sa og dna emoc spihS
.yks eht ssorca evaew scinhcetoryp eht sroloc fo tliuq thgirb eht gnillavir ylisae savnac eht ssorca gnicnad
,aroruA pleh t’ndluow kcerw suovren a ekil dnuora gnitegdif eM
,ekaseman lufituaeb ylgnikathtaerb eht ekil
.siht em gnivig rof ,ereh su gnignirb roF
:ytilaer gnimoceb ot resolc hcum os emoc tsuj sah
:ylthgils os reve tsuj tub
.enim era smraws enord
– kcab s’aroruA dniheb lla fo tsael
:pordkcab sa yks eve s’raeY weN eht htiw dnetnoc ot evah ew yadot
nottub yalP eht tih I retfa stnemom ylno
yrotsih s’ytic emoh ruo fo sraey derdnuh ruof
...tuo no ereh morf kaerb ro ekam s’tI
...edisa em dehsup ehs nehw tsrow eht deraef I
.emitefil a fo ecnahc siht sdrawot yaw ruo gniwalc otni tup ev’ew krow eht lla tnuoc uoy fi
,laitnetop eurt sti lrufnu ot eerf won
ecnetsixe yrev sti rof raw a otni noitan gnuoy a sdael
.loohcs hgih ni kcab tcejorp tra derahs a no krow ot ekil d’ehs fi reh ksa ot egaruoc eht retsum ot skeew em koot ti
...slicnep no gniwang ,liat gniggaw ,swap gnippaT
?od I dluohs tahW
”.gnorw og yllautca dluohs gnihtyna fi niaga ni kcehc ylno ;nur sgniht teL
:snoitaretla eht htiw enod m’I modeerf rof yrc s’noitan tnecsan ruo ot sdeecorp evitarran s’aroruA sa tsuJ
elcatceps laitselec eht tsdimA
.yoj tnatcepxe htiw dellif si kroY weN
,eb yam ytilaer dna noitibma etarapsid sA
– 35:32 ,rebmeceD fo ts13
:ereh su thguorb taht nosaer eht si ytilaiceps ruO
,)moc.yrrufos.okceg-hsiulb//:sptth( releeH eulB eht eiuolB yb ”3308261/weiv/moc.yrrufos.www//:sptth silaeroB aroruA“
.ekila dab dna doog
– ecneidua ruo fo secaf eht ni ti ees nac I
,ti gnissentiw srotatceps derdnuh a naht erom yaw era erehT
.sdoohilevil ruo nrae
!loof elbaroda na hcus tsuj er’uoy semitemos tub ,wonk I ruf tsetrams eht er’uoy
,sthguoht gnicar ym mlac ot gnihtemos eriuqer I oS
– reh ees I sa flesreh ees reh tel ot hsiw I
,tnessid semoceb tsrif tnetnocsid
;enola niamod reh s’ti yllausU
:eno tnelis a si dlrow s’aroruA
...reh erofeb leenk I erehw morf pu em sllup ehS
.dehctaw ydobon esuaceb tsuj etsaw ot og t’now
– sekatsim ym fo tseggib siht ydemer ot tuoba ma I ?oloX ,rednuof-
eninac detnahcne na sdnif
...rehto hcae rof tuo gnihcaer sgniward eht ni sruf eht ees nac
– dehsirep ,esrow ro
.dnim ni evah I stnemtsujda eht ekam ot tfel emit hcum evah t’nod I ;resolc sward
,ytilauqe fo sesimorp delliflufnU
:ekil sleef ecarbme s’revol a tahw si siht oS
meht ni feileb eht eldniker ot sekat ti lla netfO
,noissap derahs a emaceb ybboh derahs ruO
rethguad dna rehtoM
:worg ot snigeb tnenitnoc dlo eht morf dlroW weN eht ot thguorb sgniht fo redro eht htiw tnetnocsid eht
.efil ym fo evol eht – smaerd ym fo enilef eht si leef dna raeh
;krow ot teg yletaidemmi I nwod kcab gnittiS !si ereht dna
.skrowerif raeY weN eht fo daeha sseniddig
.emit ot emit morf rednimer a si
.rednuof-oc dna – noinapmoc detsurt
– sdnasuoht fo sderdnuh neht
dworc eht fo sreehc gnigruser eht sretsiger dnim ym fo trap tnatsid emos
!lla retfa rof dednetni s’ti eno eht rof elbisiv t’nsaw enecs artxe eht fi od t’ndluow tI
.ymene elbicnivni ylgnimees a tsniaga
– em rof naht esrow neve neeb evah tsum
...flesym dlofnu evitarran eht hctaw ot snur lairt ruo fo eno gnirud mraws enord eht gnisivrepus fo erac ekat miJ tel ev’I dna
llafdnal sekam werc sti dna
– smra nwod yal ot esufer noitan ruo fo srednuof eht gnithgif dna esaesid
.su fo owt eht sdrawot savnac gniylf ruo ngilaer ot miJ ot langis eht evig I
ereh nwoD ”!gnizama er’uoY
.emit tsrif eht aroruA tem I retfa gnol ton