.dekoolrevo I noitcesretni eht no dehsarc
.taeb eht rof kcip ot snoitpo fo ytnelp tog ev’I
.woleb roolf eht otno em werht dna
,hcturc eht htiw dnuora ssem ot
,yoj gnidnif tuoba seirots seroda eH
.sgnidit doog dereviled ylno ecivres latsop eht
?su evas lliw ohW ,seirc s’nerdlihc eht raeh ew dnA
,daerb cilrag fo paeh a dna
.rorroh dehsiugna fo etats a otni larips I tsel
,noitcidartnoc dehcterw taht rewoprevo t’ndluoc dlrow eht ni sdrac gniteerg eht llA
.gnihtyna xif t’ndluow ti taht retfa noos gnizilaer ylkciuq
;noitcurtsed fo eceip yranoisiv a
,tib elttil a rof efil ym eb ot erew siht fI
.ertaeht lacisum ni ecalp on dah I ,t’nsaw I fi ,niaga nehT
,ti ot noitnetta yap ot nageb neht tsuj I dna
.emoh gninruter etarbelec ot elanoitar dah I
.edaçaf taebpu na niatniam ot eruliaf ym tsdima reh dlot I
neht derednaw dnim yM
,esnefed-fles ni delbmum I ”,wonk uoY“
.retfa thgir emac enohp eht no gnid dnoces A
.ssecorp evitaerc eht ni yteirbos fo tnih a tuohtiw seceipretsam etaerc sosoutriv nees ev’I
.ydob ym degavar llews prahs a ,euc no thgiR
,egdirf eht fo gnirrihw eht morF
yltsenoh erom spahrep ro
.ehcysp nrobbuts ym dednammoc I
.noitacidem niap ylthgin fo stceffe edis ysword eht dna
.tnedicca eht erofeb yad eht tuo tfel dah I
”,tsoh laedi na eb ot epahs taerg ni yltcaxe ton m’I
.yaw reh no tnew ehs
.yrehcuabed eht otni flesym nworht evah thgim I
gnittes neve ro enil tolp a fo hcum os evah t’ndid I woh gnieeS
,dnats thgin nedoow ym no tas retaw eci fo ssalg lluf flah A
rehtruf flesym denut I
.sgnileef esoht etabrecaxe ylno dluow tI
.ecalp sti koot ylohcnalem derae-ypoord tub
,net litnu esod dnoces ym ekat t’ndluoc I
.esle enoemos fo thguoht eh ,tuo denrut tI
,dah I erofeb peelsa nellaf dah eh taht deciton I
.nepo emac rood eht erofeb elbatrofmoc tog dna
sdrow fo ydolem a ,nehT
.noisufnoc ni deksa I ”?eussi ,tiaW“
.em dnuora dlrow eht tuo tuc ot deirt I sa drawnwod werd srae yM
.erac neve ot tirips evitaerc ym otni peed oot raf
,xob cisum yrutnec ht02 ylrae na sa deviecrep I tahw
,tey ton tsael ta
.wonk t’ndid I ,niap lanoitome ro lacisyhp morf erew yeht rehtehW .sbos tniaf
;ti rof gnikool nehw devirra modles noitaripsnI
,tsurc yhcnurc a no seotamot luftsez dna eseehc ylbbub fo secils thgie dah I
pets rep tnecca eno
,mhtyhr rab-ruof taht tcefrep ot snroh rac erom owt detcepxe I
,duol tuo denaom I ”,tihs ,hgU“
.esion fo secruos erom raf dedivorp gnidliub tnemtrapa ym fo roiretni ehT
dlrow nettirw eht rof kcank a tog ev’yeht dezilaer yltnecer tsuj ohw ,nattalkaB nezE yb ”esioN dnuorgkcaB“
.esruoc sti nar esod remrof eht taht emac emit eht nehw langis dluow toof ym ni ynoga gnibborht eht ,ylerus tub
.snoiger rehten sih raen egac cillatem a fo eniltuo eht sdrawot derutseg eh nehw yllaicepse
.ylper ot tey dah repsaJ
kcolc golana eht sdrawot ecnalg yzad ehT
.sriatspu no gniog nuf eht ot
emit eritne eht ereht neeb dah ti ebyaM
,sdiletsum fo ygro na saw emuserp ylno dluoc I tahw dna
rehtegot swap ym dehcterts I
moordeb ym gnitarapes yawrood eht ni deppots I
”.ereht eb llits ll’ti
.sdnoces wef a rof ti etalpmetnoc did I
?su evas ot eno eht eb lliw ohW
,emoh ta thgin yreve htiW ,ecar a t’nsi ti gnidnif denrael I ,erots ni evah uoy esoprup revetahW
,thgis eht ta seye reh dellor retsis niwt yM
,ytimalac eht etagitsevni ot tuj lufecrof a htiw pu gel ym
deltit ylevitatnet
.etuhcarap a ekil tuo ydob sih gnihcterts dna
:yenruoj gnimoc siht ni sesaeler tsetaerg ym fo eno tas retnuoc nehctik eht nO
.enola dna tsol sselehtenon tub dlrow eht fo retnec eht ta er’uoy nehw
,snoitasrevnoc ruo yojne ot nworg dah I
.ecaep s’gnineve na gnitteg fo epoh yna tsol I
,elbassap gnihtemos tsael ta ro
seye gninaeb ruo tub ,detrap spil ruO
”?tahw ro azzip siht tae annog ew era oS“
.ssik a rof ni em dellup eh
,won roF .stnerap ruo dna
”?thgir siht teg reven I fi tahW“
.noitatumrep lacisum siht htiw deifsitas m’I
.lwocs a otni dnecsed dluoc I naht retsaf depoord srae yM
,htlaeh latot fo semit ta tub
.esuap a ot emac ytic eht gnirednaw fo syad ym
,thgiled ym ot hcum dna
,tfel dah I msimitpo revetahw fo nirgahc eht oT
.ti htiw nur dna noitaripsni fo derhs tsetniaf eht teg ot setunim evif naht erom tiaw t’ndid I taht neht dezilaer I tub
!ti dnif dluoc I reverehw noitaripsni dedeen I ,timmad tub
,ssendoog ysaerg eht htiw og ot initorrac a flesym dexif I
.srae ym detalumits
.rof eid ot scitsuoca dna stes gnirewot htiw nwot ni retaeht yticapac tsehgih eht
.etunim elohw a tsomla rof
nattalkaB nezE yb
laog ym degnahc I
.eludehcs no thgir daeh ym ni erif ot nageb sciryl ,yenruoj eht nI
.drawrof tnew doirep gniveirg eht sa syad gniwollof eht revo nwod looc ylbamuserp dluow eugolonom lanretni ym fo hcum ,detnarG
.ecarbme s’efil dnif I ,sgniht elttil eht nI
yrots a otni denrut eb ylbissop dluoc taht esle gnihtyna dna ,sdaerht aidem laicos ,stneve lacirotsih
.sruoh owt fo esruoc eht revo snoitisopmoc net otni denrut
”,uoy peek ot gnitnaw ton tuoba dias I tahw tegrof esaelP“
,seugaelloc wef a fo sekil eht
,yad lla tlef d’I noitome evitisop yna fo tsom eht dedivorp emaf fo tnemom gniteelf ehT
.ecuttel s’lived eht ot rednerrus fo etats a ni ylbaborp saw htols eht ,tniop taht oT
owt tas steehs eht evobA
,nattalkaB nezE yb ”esioN dnuorgkcaB“ saw sihT
,nwot ni stnemtimmoc rehto dah ehS
,yaw eht gnola seirots erom sah dna
samajap fo tnecrep ytfif ni deb ni saw I taht tcaf eht yb denetaerht erom eb dluow seitiliba gnitsoh yM
.nwod kcab sriats eht dehcaer eh erofeb dnah a rof deksa I
.trihs ruoy degnahc tsuj I ,yrrow t’noD
.egats no secneidua wow dluow enut hcae woh tuoba gnikniht
,dnim ym otni deppils gnillib lacidem no sthguoht suoixna fo lufdnah A
.nwotytnahs a fo redael lufecruoser eht sa namow eht dna
?retsasid ypmac a emoceb ton
.htiw neeb ev’I esle enoyna ni nees ylerar ev’I taht uoy ot cigam a s’erehT
.htiw nigeb ot yrujni na no drah siht flesym gnikrow eb t’ndluohs I
,noisserpeD taerG eht ni sedivid ssalc yb trapa nrot ,srevol owT
,gnireffus morf demmets tra taerg taht dias neeb dah ti
.tnemtnioppasid rof pu flesym tes I doog erew secnahc
,yrots lacihpargoibotua tsedom ylbaifitsuj a evaew ot tuolc eht evah t’ndid I elihW
.saw taht tahw wenk I neve ton
tuoba gnikniht ni tseretni on dah I efil esohw
.ssenilnaelc rof eye neek a htiw desselb saw ehs
,rewop gniyats yna dah rood ym no dekconk taht saedi eht fo enoN
.dnim ym edisni pag eht dellif I os
.yaw evissam a ni trapa dnats dluow
”?rebmemer ,tam eht rednu yek a tfel uoY“
,mhtyhr a otni spetstoof dna gnikaerc eht gnitalsnart yb nageb I
,wenk I gniht txen ehT
thguoht gnidecerp yrevE
ecnelis elbatrofmocnu na ni tas I
,pleh t’ndid meht ediseb knuks eht fo seye suoitatrilf ehT
.rood ym edistuo eot a sa hcum os tuohtiw
edis eht ot ffo dils ti taht
,taots eht htiw seirtnasaelp wef a degnahcxe I
.ot dedeen ti sa hcum sa no nips dluoc dlrow ehT
.daeh ym otni deppop tahw tuo gnittel ylpmis ot
.eno rof elbat ym ta riahc a otno depmuls I
,tiderc s’repraH oT
petstoof hcae htiw opmet rab-ruof a detaerc I
”.toof nekorb a htiw enod tol a teg ot gniog ton er’uoY“
”?thgir ,gnihtemos ekam ot deen tsuj I“ ,dedifnoc I
,levon sih fo tfard tsrif eht detelpmoc tsuj sah dna
.dniheb detfird I elihw
,roolf eht no thgin eritne eht gnidneps detalpmetnoc I erehw tniop eht ot
derettam taht llA
.thguoht ew naht regnol koot ti dna ,ecalp reh otni evom nisuoc ym gnipleh saw I
stnemurtsni dna skoob cisum teehs eht gnippetsedis
onaip draobyek ym sdrawot decnalg I sa detalpmetnoc I
.hcneb draobyek ysmilf eht ot yaw ym edam I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.rettam t’ndid tI
.ybraen dial dap revetahw otno snoitaton dna sciryl nwod delbbircs dna
,talf nattahnaM rewol ym fo rood tnorf eht sdrawot depmil I
.azziP opuL illetarF emos devarc ylpeed I
,etiteppa elbaton sih etipsed erom ynam ekat t’ndid repsaJ ,ylgnikcohS
,supo mungam siht rof ot gnilc ot daerht citameht ron
mra ym dnuora swalc sih gnipparw
.eciov edistuo sih hsaelnu ot tneve cimsylcatac a ekat dluow tI
ytsenoh didnac sih ta dehgual I
.no yrrac ot elba eb reven dluow reerac yM
,emit fo kcart tsol I
.emonortem tfihsekam a sa
emarfdeb nedoow ysmilf ehT
,driew gnikcuf era serianoilliB
,tuo no ereht morF
.looc sih tpek renwo s’rac strops dedne-raer eht sa gnol sa
,deb ym sdrawot nees reve d’I naht retsaf decap eh ”,lliw uoY“
,onaip eht ot egayov eht nI
,erutuf eht enimaxe ot yrassecen emaceb ti
,egelloc morf dneirf a
.tsethgils eht ni krow ot demees ekam dluoc I gnihtoN
.bew krad eht no ti tsil
,etar siht ta peek I fI
”?yako ,em llik ot ton yrt tsuj ,ekil d’uoy revetahw ekaT“
”?toof eno no dnuora gnippoh yako eb ot gniog er’uoy erus uoY“
,tuo gnidaeh m’I“
,egassem tsetal sih ot deppilf yllatnedicca I
,citehtap otni gnidnecsed morf flesym pots t’ndid I
.esahcrup pohs euqitna suoenatnops a ro
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,dessefnoc repsaJ ”,taht ton s’tI“
,tnanet suoiverp s’oiduts eht yb llaw moorhtab eht otni defink sdrow lanoitarri dna debrutsid eht detisiver neve I
.em dnuora dlrow eht ot ni enut ot deunitnoc I ,daetsnI
”.ydaerla nossel taht denrael I ,em eveileb ,hO“
.em detiawa niap dna noitalosed fo skeew nopu skeeW
.uoy tuohtiw nuf gnivah enoyreve ees ot truh llits ti
.raeg otni kcab dekcik yllanif tirips evitaerc ym
,wodniw ym gniteem tesnus fo seuh nedlog
.erom owt emusnoc ylippah dluow I ,dias gnieb tahT
,niaga degnid enohp yM
.noitautis a erid siht ni enola em evael t’ndluow lleh sa erus tub
,smelborp ym evlos ot lohocla no yler ot tnaw t’ndid ylniatrec dna
,stniop yhtapmys rof noitidnoc lacisyhp ym gnisu fo kcabllaf eht dah syawla I
,moordeb siht dnoyeb kool ot ton dediced I ,daetsnI
,og sgniht woh no gnidneped tub“ ,dekramer I
,tsuj s’tI“ ”?krow ot kcaB“
,shtym ,slacisum ,skoob
.ecils a dah ydaerla I mih llet ot traeh eht evah t’ndid I
.sseldrager nwod meht toj ot dediced I os ,hguorht enihs thgim htrow rieht yad eno tub ,tsael ta raf os
,rehtruf pu esle gnihtyna ssem t’ndid ti taht lufknaht ,niap ni desruc I .esod noitacidem niap tsetal ym rof eudrevo sruoh owt saw I taht em denraw
,efil yad-ot-yad ym morf em pots dluow yrujni siht taht denialpmoc I
“ – tub ,yad ysub a dah ev’uoy nehw uoy peek ot tnaw t’nod I ,yako s’tI“
.tsethgils eht ni niap eht esae t’ndid lleh sa erus ti tub
.em sediseb dratsab ylevol siht ,tnemom siht
”.emithcnul gnirud ruoh na revo rof dalas toohs siht gnisrun saw ehS
,nettog dah ti etal woh ezilaer t’ndid I .derednerrus I
.gnineve taht esle hcum ton dna
.etilletas gnivil a erew I fi sa
.detrats gnitteg tsuj gnineve lacigam a fo nemo na
,retal selcsum dellup dna niap fo spley wef A
,tnemom feirb a roF
,segadnab ni depparw dna dnuorg eht morf sehcni gnirevoh
.emit tsap gnol s’ti esuac ,em llet tsuJ ,erots ni evah uoy esoprup revetahW
,sseccus citsitra etarbelec ot ytrap a
,rebmos neetfif retfA
.enigami dluoc I sdnuos revetahw ot srae ym denut dna
.yaw etihw taerg eht no
yb em naht redlo er’uoy ,sediseB
.ytilanif sti yleman
.gnissik ot kcab thgir tnew
.etunim a naht regnol daeh ym ni detsal aedi oN
.onaip eht ot kcab poh ot
seye ym desolc I
.tsael ta tey ton
neht tnemeerga ni delkcuhc eW
,tner rieht gnikam morf yawa srallod wef a sreksub
.ssel yna truh reven enin duolc morf llaf eht tub
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ti edart t’ndluow I
edistuo amard eht pu gnicips tnemecrofne wal fo lavirra gniusne eht fi rednow I
,toof tfel ym ta nwod dekool I
,deb ym dna taht neewteb yawklaw deraelc won eht dna
,noitidnoc lacisyhp retteb yna nI
,dnats thgin-eno a otni gnilf ruo denrut evah t’ndluow laedro siht fo gnimit eht taht deyarp I dna
.reviled ot evah dluow rehtona
.em tih ot dediced ti nehw saw tahT
.taeper ylbaborp dluohs I
.sesum gnittiwnu tuo kees ot deen t’ndid I taht won
.enola ton m’I wonk llits I
,toof eno ,erom sseug I
secneuqes gnirewoprevo
,pihc a gnisuac yllatnedicca hteet tnorf ym tuoba gniyrrow tpek I elihw ,hcum dat a deregnil
htaerb sih no azzip ehT
.seciuj evitaerc eht truh t’ndluoc noitacixotni fo tib a gnirugif
.teerts eht ni sklof eht ot
.rof srallod fo sdnasuoht diap I taht lla gniodnu dna toof taht no niap erom gnittup tuohtiw toN
.ylenol tlef netfo ti
.nwo ym fo ynohpmys a etirw ot semit hguone draobyek eht no daeh ym degnab I
“ – uoy ,hu ,oS .thgir ,hO“
”.flesruoy yb dnuora sonaip dnarg evom ot yrt t’nod ,oiduts eht ot kcab teg uoy nehw ,osla dna“
.erom ro noillim a teg dluoc uoy ,kcul doog fo ngis a s’tI
.sllib yregrus eht reviled d’yeht ,keew a nI
noitpurretni gnihsarc eht ,sseldrageR
,esiwrehto yas dluow toof ym no tsac ehT
.yrots efil ym ni tniop wol a eb ylbativeni dluow tahw ni roolf drah dloc eht no gniyl
.eton dnoces yreve
.citamardrevo tib a saw I ebyaM
.gninrom eht ni edec dluow niap eht gnipoh
”.cip kcid“ a sa ot refer dluow sreep ym fo tsom gnihtemos
.erauqS semiT ot yenruoj rieht ni ruoted a no kcuts
.noisseccus tcerid ni snroh rac owt yb dewollof
.tsom rof noitagilbo na ylbaborp erew sdrac ehT
,htlaew fo ylimaf a otni nam eht gnivah yb sepytoerets redneg gnitrevbus tub
.sgel ym ni gnileef eht lla gnisol retfa gniraeh denethgieh ylbissop eht morf emac krep ylno ehT
”.lla ta gnihtyna deen uoy fi em llaC“
egalliV hciwneerG hguorht klaw d’I noihsaf emas eht ni
,ylleb lluf a dna bmil bmun a htiW
.dedeen yletarepsed os I noitaripsni eht edivorp t’ndid xob cisum eht ylraelC
,siht gniod er’uoy yhw wonk t’nod I
.noisufnoc eht ni dessap sdnoces enin fo lla fi erac t’ndid I dna
,repaid yhtlif a fo lwab gnigar s’regit elitnafni eht
.troppus eht rof mih deknaht dna
,etal os gnieb tuoba yrroS“
.did I sa gnittis eno ni eip eht gnihsinif ot esolc sa nettog evah t’ndluohs I ,thgisdnih nI
,delaeh ylluf er’uoy nehw ,uoy esimorp I
”.evitaerc erom eb ot dnet elpoep yssem dias taht erehwemos yduts a daer I“
snoisses ekoarak gniralb dna snroh rac eht ,thgindim tsap nevE
”.etirw dna ksed a ta tis ot teef htob deen t’nod I
,dlrow eht ni emit eht lla rof siht htiw nur dluoc I
,em gnirujni rehtruf esruocretni hguor tuoba yrrow ot evah t’ndid I ssendoog knahT
.emas eht tsuj deraf lla tub ,saedi yrots erom wef a htiw dereknit I .thgir dnuos t’ndid tsuj tI .epoN .nam ym eb ot detnaw uoy fi deronoh eb d’I
,skrow suoiverp ym morf sdrawA kseD amalL eht ta snaf wef a evah did I dna
.yats ot reh gniksa ylhsifles erofeb thguoht fo niart ym gnippots
.azziP opuL illetarF fo xob a htiw
,noitidnoc tnerruc ym ni retsum dluoc I guh tseb eht retfA
wodniw eht tuo kool d’I
,egar sselepoh ni toof lanoitcnuf ym depmuht I
.evots eht yb thgir wodniw nepo eht dellif dlrow edistuo eht fo ynohpocac a
.semit ta dratsab nrobbuts a eb ot flesym wenk I tub
,nehctik eht sdrawot dellorts I sA
“ – krow wohs siht ekam gnihtemos gnidnif peek attog I
.flesym ot thguoht I ”,og ,niarB“
”?dloraH ,gnimoc retaeht lacisum ni cissalc taerg txen eht s’nehw ,oS“
.nrecnoc tnetop tey
.enut eht htiw pu thguac taht oiranecs a etaerc ot decar ehcysp ym dna
,doof eht rof sknahT“
.sdneirf denrecnoc morf stxet fo spmatsemit eht yb ylno delangis ,dessap sruoH
.ti eb os ,noitazimitpo mrofeerf fo detsisnoc ylno thginot fi
.noitailimuh epacse ot naht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,dallab rewop detrotsid driht a retfA
.mih htiw meht gnidnif yojne uoy sepoh dna
sniap lanoitome dna ylenol ehT
”.nam ,kaerb a flesruoy evig ot mees reven uoY
moolrieh ylimaf a yldetbuodnu
.gniht gib txen eht eb dna yrt ot drah os gnikrow syawla er’uoY“
,tcaf fo rettam a sa
.cisum lacissalc fo srevoc redrocer dehcterw ot stcaf nuf cifitneics
.samajap otni degnahc yllacigam wohemos gnivah
,yrots a deen t’ndid I
.revewoh ,wen t’nsaw
,mihw wen hcae ot gnola gnilppit tpek toof lanoitcnuf yM
.elbareffusni em dnuof repraH
.dnim ym edisni yballul a gnisivorpmi
.yawyna edis detrevortni eht sdrawot dednet syawla I ,sediseB
.raf os tuo kcehc did ecnedive eht tub
.enivid ylurt gnihtemos etirw dluow I ,noos yad enO
,woleb steerts eht no saingisni noen eht thgil ot hguone tnatsid werg nus ehT
”.noissimrep ruoy tuohtiw ton tsael ta ,tey etiuq tleb eht woleb gnihtyna elkcat ot smret hguone doog no t’nerew ew derugif I
,esuoh detnuah detrevrep a
?uoy llet I d’tahw ,eeS“
.rehto hcae no detaxif deniamer
.em no denwad noitautis eht fo ytivarg eht
.derit tlef I nehw gnittiuq
.enihsnus eht htaenrednu ecalp ym dnif oT
.noitanosrepmi gnicnivnoc a
.ssecorp thguoht citameht ym kootrevo tnemugra neddir evitelpxe eht nehw em tsniaga denrut
.no kcab nrut ot nageb sthgil ehT
.gnitrilf yhtapmys fo tib a fo evitom roiretlu eht htiw laedro eht tuoba repsaJ dlot I
.denrut eldnah rood eht
,rehtegot dlrow eht gniees er’ew nehw dna
.tcepxe thgim eno sa llew sa tuo denrut tI
,em rof pots ot dlrow eht tcepxe t’ndid ylniatrec I
neppah maerd ym ekam dluoc I
.etad retal a ta swercs esoht nethgit ot eton latnem a edam I
talf ym ssorca kert ehT
,gnab tnadrocsid sti ni levon gnihtemos detseggus
.noitcartsid ym derehtruf
.sdubrae ym ni ynohpmys eht ot petstoof hcae emit dna
,mih ediseb thgir rebmuls a ot detfird dna srae ym ni dekcut I
;dlrow edistuo eht morf dedeen I gnihtynA
.foereht kcal ro ,slliks noitazinagro ym gnidihc elihw yad eht evas ot ni gnipeews
,sarepo paos s0891 morf soediv drawkwa dna erutluc ralupop fo sesylana deliated htiw dessap sruoH
,dlofnu efil ees dna
.mhtyhr eht tes dluoc em evoba tnemtrapa eht ni tsurht hcae htiw gnikahs
”,uoy tuoba deirrow era elpoep esruoc fO
.lacisum a otni ”noitisoP fo tuO“ nrut ot sthgir eht teg dluoc I spahreP
,etunim eht yb evisnefed werg I
,noitnevretni enivid yltnerappa fo tsrub siht htiw dluoc I revetahw tuo gnitteg saw
.noisulcnoc elbanosaer tsom txen eht ta devirra I os ,yb gnuws ehs fi dellac evah dluow repraH
.noitacidem rellikniap ym fo elttob a htiw gnola
,rood siht nihtiW
,erom ecno srae ym gnisU
?su evas lliw ohW
”.rood eht teg ot evah t’nod uoy os tam emoclew eht rednu yek a gnivael m’I ,yb gniws ot deen I fI .yrraH
htgnerts ’srae ym fo tfig ehT
nairtsedep yreve yb derettu elballys yreve raeh dluoc I
elytsefil gniniatsus-fles ,yratilos a sa nageb tahW
.skramkcehc owt deyalpsid neercs enohp ym fo renroc thgir mottob eht ,dnuow eht ot tlas erom deen t’ndid yadot fi sA
.em dessessop nietsremmaH dna sregdoR fo stsohg eht ecno enola em tfel
,oga sraey ynam mihw a no smhtyhr dna sopmet gnippilf ot detpada I
,ti wenk I erofeB
woleb éfac eht ni nemar rof sredro ehT
,taht flesym llet ot deirt I
.slennahc gnippilf sa yllarutan sa emac sdnuos gnihctiws os
?naem uoy od tahW“
,esle gnihton fi tub
sesnes lanoitcnuf ylluf ym
.sraet tsniaga elttab a ni flesym ot thguoht I
,yrujni eht erofeb nevE
airohpue erup fo snaom rieht yb deinapmocca
.elihwhtrow gnihtemos htiw kcuts I litnu
,neves tsap ruoh flah a dewohs kcolc ehT
.esol ylbativeni dluow noitcudorp a hcus srallod fo snoillim eht tuoba neht dezisatnaf I
.regnol yna em rehtob ot desaec niap ym fo stimil ehT
,ecnatsiser ym derednerrus I
.dekrans liatnottoc eht
,setalp repap
,smaerd ym no pu evig ot em gnillet fo yaw s’esrevinu eht saw siht spahreP
”.sis elttil ,emit sekat suineG“
”,ecapsretlA eht morf setoN“
.gnihtyreve fo kniht did yllaer ehS
detseggus gnikaerc dna snaom ehT
.rehgih werg stirips nehw niaga yrt ot eton latnem a edam I
,ytirecnis eniuneg htiw repraH deknaht I
.daeh sti no denrut dah
.gnieb emit eht rof yawa meht hsup ot deganam I tub
.smra sih ni dial I ,tnemom yrevE
,tirips remrof ym fo noitarotser a was repraH ,tniop siht yB
gninnips tpek dlrow eht ,thgin yrevE
.laed egakcap eht ni emac taht eelg fo skcilc elbaniatnocnu eht dna
.flesym ot derettum I ,thgin eht ffo pot ot yaw a tahW .delgrub gnitteG
,azzip deredro ,deb ni uoy toG“
ylesicerp os deppils loots draobyek eht tub
.skrow ym fo wef a dezingocer ylgnisirprus ohw
,tsap eht sdrawot gnikool fo daetsni
.yrtsudni siht ni yteiroton hcus gnihcaer fo sepoh elttil dah I
.roolf eht denroda ados fo elttob retil-owt a elihw
,evoba sdraobroolf eht gnikaerc tpek yltnerruc yeht ,daetsnI
,snossel arepo s’nevar eht neewteB
,yllacificeps eroM
,lennalf pu taeb a dna snaej deppir gnitrops ,repsaJ emac nI
.enoz eht otni flesym dehcnertne ylippah oot lla I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,dnim ym ni noitcudorp eht denoisivne I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
taeb eht htiw flesti deirrac ssecorp thguoht eritne ym
.rebmuls detsuahxe na otni gnitfird erofeb deppiuq I
sisehtopyh ym detbuod I
.railimaf ylpeed deraeppa seton eht ,wohemoS
,ssenhsiloof nwo ym fo tnuocca no yrujni siht desuac I
.gnireffus s’tsitra eht eriuqer ylirassecen t’ndid ti dna
.eb ot esle erehwyna dah I ekil t’nsaw tI
.kaerc rep eton flah prahs a dna
,ffo ti pohc dna daeha og nac uoy ,laeh t’nseod ti fi ,oiranecs esac tsroW“ ”.od lliW“
.nwonk ecno dah ew dlrow eht ot lleweraF
-- .tuo dellac eciov railimaf a ”?dloraH“
.pets eht ekat oT
,secalp ylekilnu tsom eht ni cigam dna ,ylohcnalem
?ton ti did ,rednof worg traeh eht edam ecnesbA
langis tseb eht pu kcip ot dnuora detrotnoc yltneg srae yM
,krow ot kcab teg attog I tub
,ylohcnalem gnitnuah a dekove ydolem ehT
.gnorw meht evorp oT
.teef ym no teg attog ,krow siht ekam nac I
!ecalp ruoy gniydit seod oS“
,deb ym pota tas I
,erom ecno secived nwo ym ot tfeL
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.seow evitaerc ym ot esuac a sa regnuh deniatretne I
,tnemom a rof dna ,dekcehcnu tfel nehw pu derujnoc niarb ym gniht fo dnik eht saw ztlaw lamirp A
.evol ni senivrec ot mehyam metrom-tsop morf
azzip atirehgraM toh gnipip a htiw devirra taots yreviled eht retfA
stsiruot deirrah dna
,rehtegot gnitteg sdneirf emitgnol dnuof dna ytiniciv eht dennacs I
tsael ta ,derujni saw ydobon ,yletanutroF
.esucxe on dah I nehw elihwhtrow gnihtyna etaerc ot gniliaf fo pot no
no deyalp ssergit eht yballul a derutpac srae yM
lacisum rorroh a ekam neve I dluow kcuf eht woH
,citamard wef a htiw dereknit I .onaip eht yb sgulprae fo riap a tpek I ssendoog knahT
.emit a hcus saw sihT
,seid su dnuora thgil eht sA   ?su evas ot eno eht eb lliw ohW
.tcilfnoc rehtona rof tfel ecneitap on dah tub
”!knihT ,dloraH ,knihT“
.siht ekil sthgin fo ytnelp dah I
.esion eht tuo gninword ni luftiurf yllanigram ylno devorp senohpdaeh ym eveirter ot
.wodniw eht tuo kool t’ndluoc I
nwodtnuoc s’langis gniklaw roodtuo eht htiw demit ,htuom ym sevael
,seivom etirovaf no dellewd I
”!gnizama saw eussi htxis eht fo dne eht ta tsiwt eht ,doG“
.rehto yna sa emas eht thgin siht edam tahw tuo erugif ot yrassecen t’nerew srae eht ,yaw rehtiE
.tsom eht dezilanretni I esnopser sih fo tcepsa eno eht gnieb taht rof flesym ta desirprus ,deksa I ”?eW“
.flesym fo loof a ekam flesym tel ot hcum oot pu siht depyh I tub
deudbus a htiw deksa htols eht ”?yako uoy erA“
.daeh ym ni kcartdnuos eht htiw
”,krow ti ekam ll’I“
.rehtegot efil fo tib yreve ni gnikat sepyt lla fo serutaerc
…evivrus ylerab ew dna ,sessap tnemom yrevE
,edis ym gnisserac yltneg dna
.siht lla ni emit ssap ot yaw tseb eht tuo derugif neht I
nosaer rehto on rof fi
,secnamrofrep emitemirp rieht erofeb rennid gnikees setilaicos eht meht htiw gnignirb
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.deirt I fi supo mungam siht trats ot emit retteb a fo kniht t’ndluoc I
?emas eht tsuj em evol esaelp uoy lliW
,noitanigami detsiwt reh ta dehgual eW ”.nam
,yraropmet t’nsaw ti fi nevE
,rotavele s’talf ym ot kcab depmil I nehW
”.esaelp ,bmil nekorb a evah I rebmemer ,tsuj
.pu pihw dluoc niarb ym gnihtyna naht retteb eb dluow ti ,ylniatreC
,cigam lacisum gnivaew devol I sa hcum sA
.srellikniap esod hgih fo lluf elttob a
morf sdrac llew-teg fo yarra eht hguorht detfis ehs sa em derussa repraH
.noitatnemirepxe fo tib a retfa kniht I
.thginot deneppah emag gib revetahw revo ti gnisol doohrobhgien ruo ni rab strops elos eht dna
.kcartedis yraropmet a htiw laed dluoc I
.eb ot dedeen I tahw gnirednow tpek I ,daetsnI
.won thgir mih rehtob t’ndluow I derugif I
elbitrevnoc a ,sdog eht morf ngis a fi sA
.t’ndluoc I taht em tih ylkciuq ti ,pu teg ot deirt I nehW
.htrow ruoy wonk I tub ,srallod evah t’nod uoY   .nac I
– dna ,ni kcik lliw sdem eht ,haeY“
”?setunim neves ,tahw
,nwot eht no thgin tsrif s’ylimaf a
.azzip a pu kcip ot tsuj niaga sgel ym pu gniwercs morf emit ni tsuj em devas sregnarts fo ssendnik eht ,ylikcuL
em ediseb nwod flesmih gnittes
,ofni ecnarusni ym rof gnihcraes dna latipsoh eht otni gnikcehc retfa yltrohS
.dnuora yad eritne eht nrut ot hguone devorp tsac ti lleps eht
.yteicos tneced hguorht ti ekam ot eritta hguone ylerab ni sretto yrtlus fo lufdnah a htiw ti derahs I
.elbissop sa noos sa ecnatpecca fo esahp eht ot no teg dluohs I
,tuoba eb ot thguo yalp txen ym tahw tuoba seiroeht hsidnaltuo s’dad tuoba hgual dna doom eht wollem ot niwt a tuohtiW
eht nopu tey hcnul gnillif a sa hcum os deyojne t’ndah I gnizilaeR
.tuo denrut gnihtoN
,timda ot dah I tub
,timda tsum I tub
.smhtyhr dna sopmet tnereffid htiw gnitnemirepxe dna emarf eht tsniaga ti gnippat
.nihtiw esoht dna dlrow eht lla fo wonk I
”,slaeh taht erofeb wols sgniht ekat attog uoy tub ,repsaJ htiw emit dneps ,dlrow eht ni tuo eb ot tnaw uoy wonk I ,kooL“
.ytivitisnes rieht ni sdrawpu slevel ytnewt nekat evah tsum
,uoy rof od ot em deen uoy revetahW
.tib a tsuj amardolem otni gnippils eb thgim I taht detcepsus I taht htiw dna
.htraE no gnihtyna rof
.woleb steerts eht ni renoitidnoc ria eht fo tsug yreve htiw gnola
.tca tsrif eritne na detfard ev’I erofeb peels t’now I
.retteb gnihtemos dnuof eh dnoces eht em evael dluow repsaJ
,snoitatimil owt esoht dnoyeb tub
.nigeb ot tey dah ynitsed ym tlef syawla I ,erom deen I tuB
.srae tibbar rof dengised yllacificeps dnarb a no srallod gnikcuf derdnuh ruof tneps I kniht oT
.tpada dluoc I esle gnihtyna rof esackoob eht dennacs I
,krow txen ym rof emeht doog a pu erujnoc neve t’ndluoc I fI
smhtyhr ekil-tnahc dna noissucrep sselhtur htiw lacisum citpylacopa-tsop A
”esioN dnuorgkcaB“   yojne esaelP
.secalp gniog flesym dnuof I ,yllaniF
.ti fo thguoht eht yojne did I
emit ot deganam nrut ni I hcihw ,sdraobroolf ykaerc ylgniyrrow eht no hcturc eht fo pat dna
”.thgie tsael ta saw ti erus ytterP“
.tsomla ,ni ti gnibbur saw esrevinu eht ekil tlef rood txen seinohpmys eht tub
sehcturc ym no pu kcab flesym tsurht dna
.erehwesle srae ym nrut ot dah I
tneb I .rekcufrehtom a ekil truh ti ,sseldrager tub
noitcartsid ylbissop dna ssensseltser lla etanimile ot snaem a rof gnitiaw neeb d’I
,rotcod eht yb debircserp snoisses ypareht lacisyhp morf edisA
,eman ym ot sehcir yna tuohtiW
.ti tuhs dna rood moordeb eht sdrawot deklaw eH
.em htiw srevotfel eht lla evael ot dereffo eh
.gnihtyreve tuoba tsuj ni cisum eht dnif nac uoy woh evol I“
dallab yratilos a sa nageb tahW
”?ereh ni teg uoy did woh ,tiaw
,eurt emoc dluoc maerd yreve toN
.emas eht eb reve nac gnihton wonk eW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.dlrow edistuo eht morf
!degnahc teg uoy depleh dna ,sdem ruoy thguorb
,ydegart a gnitiolpxe detah I sa hcum sA
,ecneicsoduesp fo daol a neeb evah thgim trap tahT
steehs deb eht otno enohp ym dessot I