.debrutsid eb ot tnaw ton seod eh ebyam tuB
;degrahc reven saw mih tih ohw yug ehT
.yralubacov s'xob eht fo snoitatimil eht yb delbboh yletelpmoc era ohw ,serutaerc depahser emos rof esrow si ssendrawkwa citsiugniL
tuo no ereht morf dnA
,luos a tuoba nommoC ni esum yllautca oT
.nettib dna depsarg dna
llet yllaer nac ehs llA
.taht reh sllac ydobon tub ,rebmun hctab reh ,WTA-a51kraMeneG-C2 yllacinhcet --
-- tub ,swen eht hctef ot reh deksa ylraelc yrev eH .nrot si doowtA
,gnihtemos gniyas tuoba skniht ehs nehw
.ycneiciffe gnivorpmi rof doog era strap elbaecalper ,seirtsudni lla ni ekiL
,si tnemom a taht tsaeb eht si hcuS
,srepapswen htiw ekil tsuJ
.yhw ees fo tros nac ehS
,wodiw s'namecilop a fo rood eht ot og ot sah ohw eno eht eb ot tnaw uoy od ro
.riah reh nwod gnihtooms
,retal syad eerhT
.efiw s'orimakA retroP morf rettel a si rehto ehT
-- nialpmoc t'nseod ehs tub
.cinagro dna dexaler kool stnemevom rieht
.devirra sah liam eht taht yfingis ot sgnir rezzub tnorf eht nehw swen eht gnihctef ysub si ohw
,noitamrofni gnildnah ot semoc ti nehw suineg elbats a s'ehS
.sespalloc ehs dlohserht eht dessorc sah ehs sa noos sa dna
,osla ,detcartsid oot gnitteg morf meht speeK
,elbaniart tsael ta ro
,mih derehtob ehs yhw reh sksa eH
,kool kciuq a eno hcae sevig ehs
.ylhsiggod snirg doowtA .dias sah
.goD fo ecioV eht ot ,sredaer raed ,emocleW
.3002 ecnis tfarc sih ta neeb sah ohw
.yrosnes-laud ylno llits saw tnemniatretne nehw morf kcab ,ssertca dlo na
"luos" drow eht neewteb knil a evah t'nseod xobeciov reh ,ecnatsni roF
"?uoy tsissa I nac woH .ris ,yad doog"
,ti fo spaeh taerg tuo gnidnes tuoba hcum os erac t'nod elpoep snaem elbalcycer si siht fo lla taht tcaf ehT
.ylsselesion tuo rekcilf yltsom yeht ,skraps lanoisacco ni semoc tnih eht hguoht
,yrecros no gniredrob rewop taerg
-- "luos" a tuoba klat ot deen uoy nehw ekil -- egaugnaL
.enots gnillaf a revo sah ytivarg taht rewop eht sa emas eht si
,daeh eht no tap a rof doog si hcihw
.enif a htiw mih teg ll'yeht ,pu ti kcip t'nseod eh fi ,sediseB
,ned sih morf segreme orimakA
;ti edecerp taht strap eht fo mus eht -- dematnu
,gnihtyna tnaem dna dnuora saw ti nehw kcab ,eeS
"!god dab" ,ylprahs yrev ,dias d'eh dna
.sneppah ti sa ,yltcerroc -- seveileb ehs
,tloveR olbeuP eht dna
.peelsa eb ot smees eh retal sdnoces wef a dna
,niaga eye sih sesolc eH
,gnihtyna dessim t'nsah ehS
.rehtie taht dnim t'nod I dna ,renwo na evah t'nod I
,gniht gniddehs eht s'ti
saw tuo emac tahw
.elbatrofmoc steg ehs
?rewop fo ecruos eht si tahW  .sselrewop
,doowtA ot rekcarc maharg a tuo sdloh eh dna
,gnidaerswen reh morf emoc taht stnih eht ni ylno ti fo erawa s'ehs
.stneserper drow taht tpecnoc eht tuoba kniht yllautca ot erew ehs fi erif dluow taht dnim reh ni snoruen eht dna
,desinahtue reh gnivah fo erac ekat osla lliw ynapmoc eht ,kcis oot steg ehs nehw dna fI
,eciov laer reh ,eciov reh desu ehs emit tsal ehT
.omil sih ni mih htiw ekat ot
.od ot doowtA rof s'tahT
,niaga og reh stel eh ,sdrawretfA
'.nevaeh' rof enon erofereht dna
.sgniht niatrec yas ot seirt ehs nehw sisehtopyh siht otni gnoldaeh snur doowtA
.noitcetorp tcapmi s'rac ruoy tset ot hguone doog t'nera srevadac taht wonk uoy
.ylfeirb gnidnetxe swalc sih ,tuo sehcterts dna
-- deriw si niarb reh woh t'nsi ti ;t'nseod ehs dna
,dehcatta oot teg ot desoppus t'nera uoy yhw nosaer eno si hcihw
,taht ekil ekuber a dna niap lacisyhp neewteB
-- lla retfa ,naicitilop a s'eH
gnidreh-swen rof sesu ehs xob retupmoc eht tub
.hcterts a ta setunim rof nepo seye sih fo htob gnipeek
.evael ot tnaw t'nseod eh
.reh htiw od ot tahw wonk t'nseod tsuj orimakA yltsoM
-- taorht reh ni rekaeps a s'erehT
,tnemelddufeb etelpmoc rieht dna esaelp ot erised rieht neewteb thguac
;setunim owt-ytnewt
emitrevo ni gninniw maet strops a ekil ,sgniht elttil tuoba erac t'nseod eh
,retsam reh fo smihw eht morf eerf eb ot rewop eht
yrarbil eht fo tuo gniknils ,talf srae reh
.ti gnisu pots ot swov ehS
htiw ,rettam taht rof ,gnola
.tnereffid eb lliw sihT
.gaw ot strats liat reh ti tuoba skniht ehs nehw tub
.emit siht lla ,reh dnuora lla neeb s'ti
.sdratsab era sgnieb namuh esuaceb si
.egnahc lacidar a si sihT
,ta gnisaet si eilloc eht taht gniht gnimlehwrevo siht
.eno teg dna rotaregirfer eht ot og ot hguone trams eb dluow ehs ",reeb a em hctef" ot doowtA deksa orimakA fI
-- kcots eilloc redroB fo si doowtA
-- eno dlo eht ekil %59 eb ot deetnaraug si eno wen eht
.su revo rewop a evah yehT"
.elbakramernu ylrettu ,yadseuT gnirob a ,yadseuT a s'tI
,yltcaxe ,drow taht wonk t'nseod ehs
-- gnol oot reh ekat reven yeht hguoht
,selcsum rieht lla pu esnet ot rorret hguone leef ot ytiliba ehT
,yllacitcarp tneicna
,klat dna sgel owt no klaw dluoc ti tpecxe ,gip lautca na saw ti ,no ylraE
.ti ta doog si doowtA
.ledom emas eht fo eno wen a mih dnes ll'yeht dna
-- siht eveileb ot gniog ton er'uoy
.kraP lartneC fo yrehpirep eht revo lla serutaerc depahser ot drow eht daerps nac eh
.ocsirF ta skcod eht gnifarts pihsnug azukaY a ro
.erehwyreve snezitic erutuf wollef reh rof dna
.eciov reh si rewsna suoivbo eht dna
,nettik elicod a ylbaborp saw eH
.snaem ti tahw aedi on sah ehs hguoht
.eciov nwo reh ni kaeps dna
,ertceps etihw dna kcalb elttil eht deciton eh sah roN
,devrats ro netaeb gnieb fo derit si doowtA nehw semit esoht ni ,taht si siht fo tohspu ehT
.llits ekam ot ytiliba eht ylno si ereht eninac rehtona ot ;notslaR htiw
.god a fo etsaw ,eert a fo etsaW
.msimehpue a ekil mees t'nseod tI ".peels
.spihs esoht ni pu gnikaos er'yeht noitaidar eht lla tuoba
.tneserp eht morf tcnitsid sa erutuf eht fo erawa yltcefrep si ehs ,emit tsrif eht roF
.srae eht neewteb reh selffur dna
.oga sraey dnasuoht owt tsap sedaced wef a tsuj ,saduJ ecnis siht nwonk ev'yehT
.meht wonk did ehs fi neve dnatsrednu t'ndluoc ;sdrow esoht wonk t'nseod doowtA
.etairporppa smees enon
.ti fo erom yna tnaw ot ni deggulp emit hcum oot sdneps doowtA
.ecnis detailimuh os eb ot gnihtyna enod t'nsah ehS
dnatsrednu t'nseod ehs taht snoitinifed ciretose
.emit siht eno elohw a
.yaw taht ni ton ,doowtA ton hguohtla
doowtA si eman reH .si ehs dna
-- lainem gnihtemos od ot reh deksa orimakA ,oga skeew owT
.noisufnoc ni delknirw secaf
.gnikniht meht ees nac uoy ,?reeb a hcteF
draobyek eht pu gnimmug morf ruf trohs reh peek ot
.roolf eht no sgniht lleps ot ti desu dna elbbik reh nekat d'ehs
,noisiv fo dleif reh ni noitacol yb dekram era secruos noitamrofni
.naem yllaer yeht tahw gniwonk tuohtiw ,kcab meht torrap ylno nac tub ,emit ot emit morf ,ssorca semoc ehs taht sesarhp er'yehT ".ecnatsiser
.kcab sraey owt neeb ev'thgim ti ro
,derewoc ehs sa dna ,pley reh gnikam
gnimaercs
.driaB boR yb ”goD daB“
.stluser steg ehs tuB
,doof slaets notslaR
,)syek eht no esahcrup emos swalc reh evig ot dna(
*  .xobeciov eht ,aedi revelc nmaD
.ninukaB liahkiM dna
,emusnoc nac uoy gniht a ron
-- si droW tnatropmI tsoM eht tahw swonk ehS .ot dednilb-flah
-- segamad rof eus dluow noitaroproC ehT
.semit lareves hgis mih raeh nac ehs ,dnuorgkcab eht nI
,maerts evil a sah dnasuoht net ni eno ebyaM
,god ni 'htaed' rof drow a t'nsi ereht oS
.noitnetta eriuqer taht owt ylno era ereht
,htob eert pu dnuorg dna kni
-- emulov ni sdliub gninihw reh
-- drow tnatropmi tsom a
.saniter reh tsniaga thgir egami detarbilac-eninac a stcejorp
.etal oot riah a tsuj mih tog noitaroproC eht tub
.seert fo hself eht no detnirp eb ot desu liam lacisyhp oga sraey ytfif
;srethgif modeerf era ereht swonk ehS
elpmaxe na sa ti sesu eh nosaer emas ehT
.teef reh no htrof dna kcab gnikcor
,reh gnittep s'eh won thgir dnA
,htuom sih ni ti tup yllautca d'eh
.lamron yltsom dnuos reh ekam ot dednetni saw ti
,egdirB etaG nedloG eht demmar yllatnedicca pihs regnessap taht yad eht saw tahT
:ksat ralugnis a htiw rehtegot thguorb si
?uoy t'nod ,uoy stih renwo ruoy nehw gniht emas eht yas uoY
.keew tsal taht od meht was I
,reh ot ti sevig eH
.od syawla sgod -- siht stpecca ehS  .sesigolopa eH
,tsrubtuo sih retfa sruoh wef A
.ot sah ehs won tub ,enoyna ot nekops yllaer t'nsah ehs ,notslaR fo noitpecxe eht htiW .won ,shtnom rof ti draeh t'nsah orimakA ;eciov namuh reh gnisu ekil yllaer t'nseod ehS
.boj eht htiw emac eilloc eht ,rac eht ekil dna
,tac kaeps ot sdnuos thgir eht ekam t'nac doowtA
driaB boR yb "!god daB"
.noissucnoc a yb delttar teg ot hguone xelpmoc niarb A .erutcurts lateleks namuh yleugav a
.sreh fo niarb C2 taht ni erif ot trats snoruen eht litnu
.niaga reh taeb orimakA
-- ti tup yllautca d'eh swen eht uoy hctef ot revoR deksa uoy nehw dna
,erofeb ruoh na ton ,gninethgiarts ylluferac setunim evif tneps d'ehs riah eht pu sessum gnilffur ehT
,tnesnoc rof sisab eht s'ti esuaceb
.tcnitsni latnerap sdnatsrednu ehs tub
,erofeb siht rof drow eht draeh s'ehs skniht doowtA
,tnemeerga s'rotcartnocbus rieht ot gnidroccA
,yppup a saw ehs nehW ".noisufnoc
.ti rof ypareht ot tnew doowtA --
.nosrep a rof -- suoregnad oot ro -- lainem oot er'yeht tub ,sretupmoc yb llew yrev detamotua eb t'nac sgniht niatreC
.dluoc ehs fi neve t'ndluow
,evitpircsed yllaretil si taht eman a reh sllac eH
"?uoy rehtob t'nseod tI"
.detaerc yeht tahw fo esuaceb tub
,.P notslaR ot txen gnidnats s'ehs esuaceb ,elbirret sllems tnemnorivne lacol reh
seriuqer ,god a rof
-- seye reh ot sraet gnirb ot hguone drah reh tih orimakA ,sruoh
-- eriaf-zessial seidobme notslaR ".rehtie
,syas eh ,lleps cigam siht kcolnu ot drow eht nrael seod ehs fI
.esle gnihtemos s'ereht naem I
;daerps lliw drow eht taht ees nac ehS
.yliratnulovni etiuq ,enihw ot gnitratS
-- notslaR ot tsesolc s'ehs swonk ehs tub
seciton eh gniht tsrif ehT
.erus t'nsi doowtA
,syas nam eht ",lrig dooG"
reh rof ,egnahc lliw dlrow eht ti gniyas ni taht swonk ehs dna
dereviled-dnah semoc swen tseb eht
,erom esiarp s'orimakA eulav yam doowtA .krad dna thgiL
.ned sih otni dna
.illeb susuac a sa ti ekat ,esrow ro
.mih llet ot esimorp ot reh steg eH
.eye eno snepo notslaR
,deltsirb ehs dna
.gnidnammoc erom dna tnanoser erom ,repeed si eciov larutan reH
.evitpircsed si egaugnal rieht dna
.dnim eht fo modeerf rof ,wal rof
.ssergnoC latnenitnoC eht dna
:meht yas ot seirt ehs nehw dna
,tnatsnoc lasrevinu eht tuo erugif ot seirt ehS
.stsirbmeceD eht dna
,sdaeh rieht tlit ll'yehT
,drah ,reh sevohs eh nehT
-- weivdlrow ruo stcelfer egaugnal ruo taht syas tI
,tnemom eht ni sevil osla flesreh doowtA
.ti ni sdik ruoy htiw renil latibro eht rO
-- flah ni ti gnittuc
,stuanortsa kcots-tac 2C eht evah uoy yhw s'tahT
-- revo dlrow eht dnik rieht dna sgnieb depahser esoht rof tnatropmi tsom spahrep tnemom eht
,yas ot gnitseretni gnihtemos sah dnasuoht derdnuh a ni enO
,ylhguor ,snaem ti dna hsiugnitsid ot elba eb reven dluow uoy krab gnirevaw a s'ti
.efiw sih morf rettel eht gnidaer-er dna gnidaer
,revo srettel eht sdnah ehs nehW
.edutitalp a tsomla s'ti
,ti yas lliw ehs taht swonk ehs siht naht erom dna
.mih gnitnioppasid si gniod s'ehs lla gniyaled yb dna ,yletaidemmi ti detnaw eh ebyaM .seod eh ebyaM
.ssendnik fo lobmys ytpme na ni ytivarped rieht edih ot wonk nem esaB
,hsaWsoB rof snoitaleR remusnoC fo tnediserP eciV etaicossA eht
-- "cod ,enif leef I" yas nac ohw ydobemos deen uoY
,stcnitsni gnidreh esoht lla
,ned sih nI .enod s'ehs dna
.krow ot kcab seog ehs os ,detcartsid oot s'eH
,ecapslaer ni sgniht daer ot stnaw ehs fI
,kcab og srae reH  .esiurb ll'ti
.rebbols tuohtiw dna
,mih tsniaga pu eilloc thgils eht gnillup
"?dnim uoy t'noD" .swollof ehS
,si retupmoc reh erehw yrarbil eht ot kcab speerc doowtA
,reh no elzzum a tup d'eh nehT
orimakA ",doowtA ,swen eht em hcteF"
,driaB treboR yb ”goD daB“
.evisneffo ssel tib a era taht sllems sreffo -- esle gnihton fi -- hcihw ,krap eht ot seog ehS
-- seitiliba reh htaeneb saw esingocer dluoc ehs neve gnihtemos
"?su llik nac yeht naem uoY"
ro "sthgir namuh" fo gnihton yas ot
.deohce eb lliw ti taht
.ruoh na sertemolik 05 yb desaercni srac fo deeps egareva eht sa neve
;etuca etiuq si gniraeh s'doowtA esuaceb yltsom si sihT
.noisufnoc lanoisacco emos fo ecruos a si rae thgir esohw eno eht"
,ti yas ot ytiliba eht tuohtiw tuB
,gnirevihs ,revo lla gnilbmerT
,sseldnuos ,serutcip llitS
.gnihton yletulosba naem lliw ti taht swonk ehs dna ,ylevixelfer ,lotsip a ekil
.stsetorp rieht evohs nac yeht erehw dlot teg sepyt gnigguh-elahw eht oS
.setunim net ni tsegid nac ehs sdeef eht ssecorp ot sruoh evlewt nretni na ekat dluow tI
.kcen reh fo ruf desopxe eht gnittep
lennek reh ot reh tnes d'eh neht
-- retupmoc a htiw cinam os t'nera elpoep tsoM
,rulb a eb dluow
sdlrow-htiw-rereknit lareneg dna ,rekampam ,retirw a si ohw
.psarg etiuq t'nac ehs tpecnoc eugav dna suoiretsym a fo
.emoh t'nsi orimakA retroP taht emit eht fo tser eht rof ,eerf s'ehs neht dna
.owt ro tsetorp a rof doog er'yeht ,erus
.erofeb sah reve ehs naht retsaf
.rood eht smals dna ,moor eht fo tuo
dellac yrots a uoy gnidaer eb ll’I yadot dna ,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,teN eht ot thgiarts setadpu-orcim gnitsop yltsom
,daed eht dna gnivil eht tuoba yltnereffid klat ton od yeht tub
.daeh sih revo elttob a dehsams ydobemos dna thgifrab a ni tog eh ,ni skeew owT
mih ekam -- secalp ni ,enob ot nwod tuc saw eh -- sracs ehT
;etal oot s'ti litnu ti detciderp evah t'nac ehS
,ti syas ehs nehW
,tsilanruoj a si kcolf namuh elohw eht ni ydobyreve syad esehT
.wob thgils a htiw gnidnats dna mih ot gniddon
pmocixelf elbamusnoc ylisae na otni noitamrofni gnitaelb yltneg fo stib dnasuoht ytfif gnillarroc
.swen eht esisehtnys dna weiver ot setunim evif-ytnewt reh koot ti -- ecno tsuj -- ecnO
ti gniwonk ruoy tuohtiw uoy ot nevig si taht gniht A"
.devlovni teg lliw sreywal ,seid eh fI
.yawyna boj reh si hcihw ,swen eht hctef si od ot reh deksa s'eh lla dnA
,erusaem doog rof ,crA'd naeJ tuoba sdaer ehs neht dna
.noitarebil fo ssecorp wols eht nigeb ot
.gnidnatsrednu fo kcal a gnikram sa
;niaga gaw ot strats liat reH
.niaga tcnitsni gnidreh eht s'ti -- reh srehtob taht ,weksa era sgniht nehW
,riaffa eht ni tseretni detaleb a gnikat ,tsilanruoj a ;sraey lareves rof neppah ton lliw tI
-- noitamrofni esinagro ot derb s'ehs dnA
.noitaroproC latibrO eht yb denwo
.tnaveler tsom eht ylno era seirots eht dna
.detrams llits taht eson a dna tae ot gnihton htiw
.hguoht ,snamuh dnuora ti gnisu dekil reven sah doowtA
reh thguac eh nehw dna
.dnuora notslaR tnaw yllaer t'nod
.yppah-reggirt ytterp er'yehT
.retal shtnom xis noohpyt a fo deepsdniw eht ot yaw eht lla sgniw s'ylfrettub a fo gnippalf eht kcart nac taht sretupmocrepus evah ohw ,stsiciteneg fo hcnub a erih uoy ,trams yllaer er'uoy fi dnA .ro rehtiE ".sgel
,tnemom eht ni yllauteprep evil taht serutaerc era sgod esuaceB
.etacinummoc ot noisserpxe laicaf no ylivaeh yler
,tpecnoc siht htiw detaicossa drow a
.parcs lanoisacco eht ni steg dna
-- nemow sekil osla eH
.gnikniht redro-dnoces seriuqer taht drow eht fo esu railucep a
-- tnanosnoc laibal yksep taht fo esuaceb ",noituloh'er"
.ysae laer s'ti ,taht retfA
-- sreh esohc doowtA sa emas eht ,yletarebiled ti esohc eH
;reh rof noitacinummoc reh seldnah waj reh ni pihc retupmoc ehT
.lworg enilef detcartsid a htiw
.noitamrofni no egrog ot strats ehs dna
,dna ,od ot gnihton evah meht tuoba smra ni pu teg ot desu ohw elpoep eht tcnitxe lla era selahw eht taht woN  .lagel yltcefreP
.enobwaj reh ni detnalpmi ,retupmoc a morf semoc hceeps reh tub ,labrev si doowtA
nworB nhoJ tuoba sdaer ehS
.nommoC ni gnikaeps ot semoc ti nehw
.gnidnim htrow t'niA"
.dnik nwo rieht tsgnoma esu yeht egaugnal eht ni retteb yna t'nsi tI
-- yllacitenohp ti gnicnuonorp tsuj s'ehs
,dnatsrednu ot redrah osla s'ti tuB
-- drah -- reh kcurts d'eH
.eb dluow repsihw a ekil -- teiuq yllaer emulov eht etaludom ot seirt ehs tub ,hcum oot naem t'ndluohs ti ,gniht llams a hcus s'ti dna ,noitnetta sih teg ot sah ehs woN
hsart fo tib a pu kcip repeekpohs eht ees nac ehs tluser a sa dna ,mih ot txen sdnats doowtA
.ksir eht htrow t'nsi tI
,ystna elttil a teg ot gnitrats si doowtA  .setunim ytnewT
,reh kcurts dah eh nehT
-- ot gnulc eb lliw ti tahT
.etilletas a deloh ev'thgim taht gnihtemos tuo sekat dna ,kciuq
.tac eht ta ti worht dna
.muludnep eht fo kcit hcae htiw setunim eno-ytnewt ,setunim eno-ytnewt ylraelc etiuq mih gnillet eb dluow hcihw
,smetsys ytefas fo rengised trams a er'uoy fi tuB
-- tuo gnieb "gninrom dooG"
-- meht ees t'nac ehs esuaceb ,doowtA ot gnitcartsid lla ta ton era taht sruoloc thgirb ni hsalf dna ecnad ot strats meht fo eno
meht morf snrael doowtA tahw ,yltsoM
.emit tsrif eht rof gnikaeps erofeb ,elihw a rof desitcarp doowtA
.elttil yrev yas ot si hcihw
.eciohc suoicsnoc a s'tI
.revo stort dna yrarbil eht sevael ehs ;gnitpmet s'tI
,suoladnacs elttil a si hcihw ,sehtolc raew t'nseod eH
,hsilgnE ni etacinummoc ot gniyrt er'uoy fi ton tub ,kwahoM gnikaeps er'uoy fi enif si hcihw
,deugirtni eb ot smees efil sih ni ecno rof ohw
,)dnim reh ni neve ,ti srosnec ehs( g-d d-b
.lla ti dniheb nrettap eht ees ot
,stsixe taht lleps cigam a si erehT
.deen uoy sdrow eht evah t'nseod yllaretil egaugnal eht tpecxe
,esruoc fo ,sessenisub lacol ehT
snoitaleR remusnoC fo PV eht rof
.ot evah t'nseod ehs
*  .deedni ,lrig dooG
,driew elttil a sa nees s'ti taht gnieb rehto eht
,tneserp era yeht taht wonk sgoD
od snamuh larutan ekil
.ti ot netsil ot gnivah ,egde eht ot mih dehsup tahw s'tahT
.snetsil eh dna ,semitemos mih ot sklat dna semoc ehs tuB
...siht ekil rehtegot ti eceip ot trats lliw
-- sgniht hcus tuoba thguoht ehs fi ,yllautcA
,od ot serohc emos sah doowtA
suoregnad ylthgils kool
-- snamuh rehto ot od t'ndluoc dna dluoc uoy tahw tuoba selur eseht lla pu edam snoitaN detinU eht
.desahc eb ot deen t'nseod reeb a tuB
.gnilwarb ekil seod eh tub
.ecnerefnoc sserp tsetal sih ni tuoba no gniremmay si gnoK gnoH fo OEC eht tahw tuo erugif ot emit eht evah t'nseod orimakA ekil nam tnatropmi nA
liat reh -- neeb reve sah ehs tseippah eht si ehs dna
niaga drawrof gnikcilc kcolc eht no dnah etunim eht fo dnuos ehT
,ytreporp etaroproc yllacinhcet llits si eh tub
,tnecca yvaeh a htiw kaeps yeht yltneuqesnoC
.yllaciots snis ruo raeb yeht ,emas eht lla tub
,deniart llew si god ruoy fi
-- esruoc fo ,haissem a ton si god ehT
,lennek reh dna doof rof meht seciovni eh dna sllib tev reh srevoc hsaWsoB
.mih derebmemer ydobemos nehw gniniart ecaps rof mot a fo hcum oot ydaerla saw dna metsys eht ni dialsim tog eh tub
-- tuoba gniklat er'yeht tahw wonk esoht fo tnecrep net ylno dna
;efink llud a ekil gnihtemos si retupmoc eht fo citsalp eht -- struh sihT
,sgniht ni seneg namuh gnittup trats uoY
,tnemevom reh sedepmi ti raf os sgel reh neewteb dekcut liat reh
.egarevel rof doog si eh ,tuanortsa na sa sselhtrow s'eh hguoht neve dna
,noisiv reh tcerroc ot sessalg laiceps sdeen doowtA
,saedi ni snigeb noilleber ,elpoep roF
.eucser reh ot semoc tnemom eht ni gnivil ,ereH
-- tnereffid gnihtemos naem dluow taht oga sraey ytfiF
.sgod rof syawtsael
.luos a evah ot stnaw ehS
.lworg tnalutep a mih gnivig
,notslaR llet ot seirt ehS
.gnihtyna ro rotide na tuohtiw
.suoicirpac era elpoep taht si
,osla srenwo ruo era ohw elpoep eht fo renwo eht si ohw eno eht yb
,god dab a reh sllac eH
.egreme ot gnitrats si erutcip gib eht
.xobeciov eht no ecnedneped reh fo reh seerf ti dna
,repeews a ni pu ,tacortsa na eb ot dednetni saw notslaR
.gninokcer a rof ydaer eb retteb d'uoy ,llew
.yad eht fo tsom rof ti raew reh edam dna
.nehw wonk t'nseod ehs tub
lla ta tsixe reh ekil srehto dna ehs nosaer ylno eht taht edulcnoc dluow ehs
.strahc eht ffo eb dluow ti
,hguoht ,revelc tog srotaerc reh erehw s'ereH
-- tniop a ot denoh
.laiceps wohemos erew taht owt fo tsrif eht kcip ot revresbo edistuo na eriuqer lliw ti
-- htaerb rof gnisuap fo tibah gnitcartsid rieht ot noitnetta sllac tI
.)ot sah -- esruoc fo ,sbmuht elbasoppo sah ehS
",doowtA ,swen eht em hcteF"
-- stcaf no yleritne sesucof gnidreh-swen reh nosaer eno si sihT .hsirebbig
,gniklus llits ,nehw retal sruoh wef a niaga htob meht enod d'eh dna
,dlo si noitaroproC eht dna hsaWsoB neewteb yrlavir ehT
,dethgilhgih era noitamrofni fo stib tnatropmi eht llA
-- gniniart reh fo llA
.ynamreG ,nilreB ni talf a speek eh
,eugnot nommoC eht ni "llik" ot ytiliba eht tuoba klat nac ehs yhw si sihT
sda esoht htiw nam eht ,orimakA retroP
.su morf yawa ti sekat ti ro
.eerf eb ot snaem ti tahw dnatsrednu
.no retupmoc reh tfel sah ,noitcartsid sih fo tnid yb ,orimakA
,ni deggulp er'uoy fI
.yas selknirw esoht tahw si ",hctamsim tseuqer/tcejbO .rorrE"
.seitilibissopmi lla era v dna ,f ,b ,p ,m erehw
.gnisruc eht elffum ot hguone ton s'ti tub ,kcab yaw
,swen eht rof reh sksa eh nehW
*  .ti fo dne eht ta nocab laicifitra fo pirts a dna tap a naht erom meht evig ot evah d'uoy ,sulP
.ti sepahs osla ti tub
.rehtona morf gninrom eno hsiugnitsid tonnac yeht ,yltnereffid ti gnibircsed morf edisa tub
-- eman reh fo trap "C2" eht s'tahT
.setunim ytnewt naht erom reh nekat reven sah ti
.ni gulp ot emit eerf rieht esu slamina depahser fo tol A
.saw yvne tahw dootsrednu ylthgir ehs fi ,yvne dluow doowtA taht esae fo dnik a s'ti
,ikahK si eman yM
.kni cixot htiw plup deird eht pmats dna
.nossel a reh hcaet ot enod era sgniht eseht ,yroeht nI
?ti t'ndluow yhw -- sgaw liat reh oS
.tnecrep evif gnissim eht tuoba sksa reve ydobon ,sediseB
.ti ni thgiew reh htrow eb d'ehs ,dradnats dlog a ot deggep llits erew gnihtyna fi dna
,siht lla sees doowtA
,esahc nac yeht sirbed fo tib elttil a pu sthgil
,meht nethgiarts ot detrats ehs oS
-- ertemillim eht ot noitartenep scitsillab gnitaluclac
.reh htiw laed ot sah eh yhw wonk t'nseod eh taht syas eH
s'eh ;elbanoitcejbo gnieb ruodo sih pleh t'nac )LAR-17itrumirT-C2( notslaR .dneirf a fo tros si ohw
.retsaf evom yeht -- rethgirb t'nera seno rehcir eht dna
.lacisyhp eht no sredrob taht ynoga na gnicneirepxe ,won yb ,si doowtA
alednaM nosleN dna
.hguorht tros ot tol a saw ereht
.gnitrecnocsid os od ot eruliaf reh dnif ot mees yeht
,reh rof sselgninaem yllacitnames s'ti
-- tnaw uoy tahw meht llet uoY
.niarb reh ni rehtegot snoitcennoc devorppanu esoht gnirb thgim taht txetnoc fo pool kcabdeef eht sreves yltaen xobeciov reh ,sthguoht
,teprac eht ffo ,eceip yb eceip ,ti tae ot gnilliw neeb t'ndah ehs nehW
.reh ta
.egaugnal fo rewop eht s'taht
.xif ot derehtob reven kraMeneG hcihw
,seerga yllufitud ehs dna ,ti eldnah ot doowtA sllet eH
.ralloc nwo reh ot yek eht nevig eb thgim ehs gnikniht sa suolucidir sa s'taht ,llew
,htob meht enod d'eh yawynA
.esrow neve si hcihw
.mih dlot reven s'ehS
.rehtie tuoba gniklat s'ehs tahw aedi tsrif eht t'nsah eh ro seergasid notslaR rehtiE  "?luos A"
,rewop sah taht tpecnoc a si erehT
.etal oot eb lliw ti tahT
.etalucitra ot drah s'tI
.ylizal gnitfird liat
.troffe yna eriuqer t'nseod gniklat
.eciohc tluciffid erom neve na secaf ehs woN .dnuora nrut t'nseod eh tub ,retupmoc eht tuo sdloh ehS  .yltruc yrev ,sksa eh "?ti si tahw" -- d doog a eb ot stnaw tsuj ehS .yppah eb ot mih stnaw tsuj ehS .htaerb s'god eht fo noitalahxe suovren hcae skram taht enihw eht si
sthguoht nwo reh kniht ot rewop eht
,tnemom dnoces eht tuB  .lliw ehS
;oot ,reh rof desimitpo neeb sah erawtfos ehT
.egatireh dnalgnE weN duorp a ot pu gnivil tuoba klat taht
,ylraelc ,yas nac ehs drow a s'tI
,tuo secnal ti litnu dnuora resal eht fo yrotcejart eht gnirb ot stekcor eht gninrub
.wonk t'nseod ehS
.trela meht speek ti
ihdnaG tuoba sdaer ehS
,ned eht edistuo kcolc rehtafdnarg eht ta gnikool eb t'nac eh snaem hcihw ,reh ot si kcab siH
.rettal eht ni noitom fo ecnesba eht nopu kramer ot tpecxe
,esarhp detah tsom taht rof barg lliw orimakA taht ees nac ehS
.tniop noitamalcxe dehsinif-flah a ekil ,tils lacitrev ,niht a si lipup ehT
,doowtA dna mih tsuj sevael tahT
,rehtie ,rac sih nwo t'nseod eh ,neht tub
,emas eht yats ot gniog s'gnihtyrevE"
,plup otni meht hsam ,seert nwod tuc ot desu yeht
?woc denmad a toohs ot tnaw t'ndid ydobemos esuaceb deid dnabsuh rieht taht meht gnillet
-- t'nseod ti dna -- sdrow thgir eht dah hsilgnE fI
,dlo siht s'ereht ,ees uoY
-- xobeciov reh tuohtiw
,keew eht gnirud dna
,nerdlihc fo hctaw peek ot esu yeht sdranreB tniaS ywollip ,tfos eht fo eno ekil ,god C1 A
.naf eht tih ot tuoba s'ffuts eht taht esnes yeht nehw
ecnuonorp emit ni lliw ehs hcihw
,ylmodnar sneppah
,noitpecxe taht htiW
...lortnoc meht sevig tI
;esrow struh hcihw erus t'nsi doowtA
-- gnihtemos gnissim s'ehs taht tcaf eht dnuora niarb reh gnipparw fo elbapac yllaer neve t'nsi ehs ,ekorts tselleurc eht nI
;gnithgif naht retteb sekil eh sgniht wef eht fo eno si nuS
;tnecs niatrec a si ytitnedi reh sgod fo egaugnal eht nI
-- noitulover a dellac gniht a si ereht swonk ehS
,hcraeser sciteneg deilppa fo sedaced fo tcudorp eht
.esimorp fo lluf si eno sihT
.snamuh ton" dna "snamuh" llits s'ti yad eht fo dne eht ta tub ,sregit dna sgip dna swoc dna sgod dna stac depahser era ereht ,eruS
swap reh revo sevolg niht emos sllup ehs hcihw gnirud
.doolb eulb eht dna -- yarps tlas eht etsat nac uoy
.tuohsaw a revo emirc ytreporp a etucesorp ot tnaw t'ndid noitaroproC eht
,skniht ehs ,eb tsum erehT
,tuoba gnikniht neeb s'ehs tpecnoc xelpmoc dna taerg tahw swonk ehs ylneddus dna ,syas orimakA
.ecno ,eciov larutan reh htiw gniklat deirt ehS
.pihs repeews a fo stes RADIL eht ot ni deriw yltcerid sniarb rieht htiw ,sgrobyc yllacitcarp
.)no eldnah a tog yllaer t'nevah llits yeht gnihtemos s'taht(
?ti tnaw llits eh seod
.ytinrete otni revo spit ti sa
.lrig doog a syawla t'nsi doowtA
,era yeht tahw gnieb stner ,tub ecalp gnillewd sih si ecaps peeD
.noitats hcraeser a rO
.daer ot strats ehs dna ,ni sgulp eilloc redroB eht
,gnikrow yllaiciffo ton si orimakA retroP taht snaem hcihw ,yadrutaS a s'tI
,ecnatsni rof ,woN
.erac ralucitrap yna tuohtiw meht taert ot elpoep segaruocne ytilanommoc taht dna
,desucof-tneserp era sgoD
,ti rof deksa eh retfa setunim flah a dna neetneves orimakA ot revo swen eht sdnah ehS
-- reh morf tsafkaerb reh llup ot deirt eh nehw mih ta deppans tsomla dna delrihw d'ehs ,oga shtnom xiS
-- meht fo owt eht ,nommoC kaeps yehT
;cinocal eb ot mot eht rof nosaer a yllaer t'nsi erehT ".t'noW"
,dnuora slrihw eh
.egareva no ,sraey owt tuoba evil stacortsa 2C
.lla ta deciton t'nsah orimakA
wef a ro sraey wef a ,oga emit emoS  .kcuts s'ehs
.ti tsniaga hsurb sregnif s'nam eht sa ylippah tuo yalps ot hguone ,won retteb s'tI
.ssendnik ralucitrap yna yb no thguorb esae na t'nsi sihT
-- sreylf tnemesitrevda wef a sediseB
"?uoy tsissa I nac woH .ris ,yad doog"
.tlusni na sa tnaem tub
.niaga taht od reve ,reven tsum ehs taht reh dlot dah eh
.ti tuoba gnikniht emit drah a sah ehs
.citsitra dnuos dluow noitalsnart a
,seirots tnaveler tsom eht ot nwod deworran si dleif eht ecnO
daeh eht no tap a teg t'nseod ehs snaem hcihw ,tsrif sserdda nruter eht daer ot emit eht sekat eh
-- gninrom a fo llems dna dnuos eht tuoba citeop xaw yeht ,sevlesmeht neewteB
,reh rof ,citamoidi s'ti tuB
.gnillor ydaerla si llab eht litnu
-- wap dehctertstuo na ni ti gnidloh
.oot ,rehto hcae llik yehT"
,doowtA evah uoy yhw s'tahT
;seno tnereffid wef a seirt ehS
-- doowtA nwo yllaer t'nseod eH
-- emit fo gnidnatsrednu laer a tuohtiw
...emas eht lla dnA
.lacitnedi yllatnemadnuf eb ot syad lla seveileb eh nosaer emas eht si
.esle gnihtyna naht retupmoc a ot gniklat ekil erom tol a si sgod tsom ot gniklaT
.gnikirts etiuq reve tuohtiw gnilcric
.sisehtopyh frohW-ripaS eht dellac yroeht laicos ni gniht detidercsid yltsom
.god nrael ot yzal oot si notslaR dna
,krap eht fo ssarg eht sdrawot ylffits selbma dna ,sgurhs tsuj mot eht daetsni tub ,ecnats gnithgif a otni teg ot mih stcepxe doowtA ,tnemom a roF
,snoitcartsba htiw doog t'nsi doowtA elur a sA
.)doowtA ot gninnuts ylralucitrap t'nera stesnus(
.sgel ym leef t'nac I ,em pleh ,cod ,tsirhC" ro
.yllauqe ni nekat eb lla nac snossel rieht
".gnissim er'ew gnihtemoS .si ti tahw wonk t'nod I
,detaes si orimakA
.sediseb avilas fo tfig dedda na htiw
.dnif nac ydobyna taht seneg namuh yna evah t'nseod ti dnA
,rettil sih tuoba tespu si orimakA
,teef s'renwo sih ta ti pord dna
-- dekcoc syawla saw rae thgir reh
-- llems eht gnikilsid tuoba ytliug tib a sleef syawla doowtA .tac a
.tnereffid eb ot sgniht stnaw ehS
.lla dna snac nworht
.weksa ylthgils erew eceipletnam eht no serutcip eht taht deciton doowtA keew tsaL
.gnidaer ot kcab steg ehs dna
tnemidepmi hceeps a ekil si rae gnivahebsim A
emit ni nezorf tsomla sah tnemom eht taht tpecxe
.esruoc fo ,eugnot nommoC eht ni s'taht dnA
.gnihtemos ro ,tsicar elttil a tsuj saw ti ekil
,trap rieht rof dna
,ynituM yopeS eht tuoba sdaer doowtA
.wollof taht esoht fo esimorp eht
,egaugnal ngierof a ni kniht ot gnivah ekil s'tI .gnihton
.nam dlo na fo eciov eht
,ylsuoigidorp noitamrofni gniruoved si ehS
no delttes ehs -- "orimakA"
.knird a hctef ot ti llet uoy fi dexommulf eb lliw
,stnemom wef a rof ylteiuq srepmihw ehS
yrots eht ot gninetsil neeb ev’uoY   ".oN"
.noitanod llams a rof nruter ni gum eeffoc a gnisimorp
.sserdda bew gnizama na tsuj si hcihw ,god-tod-gnitirw ta tenretni eht no mih dnif nac uoY
,yllevarg si eciov siH ".gnidnim
,reh tuoba ssel ro erom era stiw reh ecnO
,yarra resal BGR na si rotcejorp ehT
;slamina ot noitcartsba na si emiT
.rae namuh eht ot elbigilletninu tsomla
.snoitalucitseg sih fo eno ni ti htiw reh gnikirts ,flah ni ti sdneb dna wap reh morf retupmoc eht spir eH
;ecalp tsrif eht ni rab a ni saw eh yhw notslaR deksa reven sah doowtA
,doowtA ekil sgodrepus enatco-hgih neve ,sgod
.tsap eht ni deneppah raW yranoituloveR eht dna gnisiR retsaE eht taht si
.rekcarc maharg fo tib a ro
,yrtne atad dna gnilif fo ruoh na ebyam s'erehT
,SRI eht morf si enO
;ecnatsni rof ,sdiam doog yrev t'nera sgod
,yppah mih ekam ot stnaw llits ehs taht eurt s'tI
.gip aeniug a evah uoy retal sraey fo elpuoc a dna ,taht od uoY
-- doowtA ot seod ti sa mih ot hcum sa snaem 'keew tsaL'  ".keew
?atrakaJ ni tnemesab s'yug emos fo tuo tsacorcim a dna erutcip ylimaf a neewteb ecnereffid eht s'tahw
;reh ot emas eht lla s'tI ?keew tsaL ?yadretseY ?gninrom sihT
,syad eseht setunim neetfif ro net sekat ylno swen eht gnihcteF
.ecnatsiser tneloiv-non ,evissap"
.dneirf tseb s'nam eb ot desoppus era yeht fi neve
.uoy dnim ,sneipas omoh naem tsuj t'nseod taht dna
.riah reh selffur eh nehw s'taht
.peels ot tup" gnieb fo noiton eht htiw tnetnoc era yehT
tar a revo sah reirret a taht rewop ehT
.lla retfa ,god a s'ehS
.002 fo QI na ;seirutnec owt
,ecnegilletni s'doowtA erusaem ot deirt uoy fI
-- etal oot mih ot gnitteg yb pu dewercs noitaroproC eht esle gnihtemos s'taht
-- star eht rof mih evael dna mih toohs ot naht erom gnihton ekil dluow syug ytiruces ehT
.syawla toN  .yltsoM
.rehtegot emoc seceip eht llA
*  .sdrow nwo reh ni skniht ehs
.gnihtyna od t'nod ecilop ytiruces hsaWsoB eht tub
keew tsal neeb ev'thgim ti
kool dekcohs sih nekat d'ehs ,tsrif tA
.reh sah orimakA yhw s'tahT
*  .mih brutsid ot naht retteb swonk ehS
.trap taht deredisnoc yllaer t'nevah stsitneics citeneg ehT
.tsonsalg dellac gnihtemos tuoba sdaer ehS
'.meht' susrev 'su' ,tcurtsnoc driew a s'tI ".su
-- tuo ti serugif ehs nehw
,ylwols ,pu steg eH
.ot elba eb thgim ehs litnu yawa slerriuqs tub
.redro rof tcnitsni s'god gnidreh a htiw ,god gnidreh a
,ti tuohtiw etarepo thgim ehs taht kniht oT
.dreh ot sgniht fo tol a fo lleh a llits s'taht tub
tseb ees nac ehs sruoloc eht ,selprup dna seulb ni sgniht swohs ti tub
,retupmoc elbixelf ,niht a no
-- smelborp meht evig taht stnanosnoc laibal eht s'tI
.lla ta noitseuq eht rewsna ot reh rof gninaem tuohtiw
.noitucolmucric drawkwa dna yhtgnel
.seod ehs sa hcum sa ti etah tsum eH
.neppah lliw tahw ees nac ehS
.erofeb meht tuoba daer s'ehs
.htoob enohp a fo ezis eht tuoba noitpartnoc ekil-niffoc a
,eetnaraug doog a si tnecrep evif-yteniN
.edam eht dna srekam ehT ".snamuh
,riah reh otni deraeppasid yeht litnu dennip srae
.stcaf ni slaed orimakA
,dlrow desilivic erom ylthgils a ni ,yadoT
,sdrow tnatropmi fo tol a tuo tfel ev'yeht tuB .skaeps ti
",modeerf" redisnoc ylisae t'nac ehS
.gniht ynnuf a si
niatrec gnitalucitra morf reh stneverp ti esuaceB
ta deffins eb nac taht sgniht elbignat no
.depmaws yltneuqerf si orimakA
,erofeb draeh s'eh gnihtemos t'nsi tI
-- lohocla knird t'nseod eh ,slamina tsom ekiL
.retsaf sgaw liat reH
.ni gulp ot euc reh s'taht
".uoy morf taeb tonnac renwo ruoy tub elbaulav si taht
",swen eht hctef" syas eh nehw dnA
lwarps ot ecalp wen a sdnif notslaR
-- !shtfif ruof -- %87 yb deppord stnedicca rac ni shtaed citamuart fo rebmun eht ,0402 dna 0302 neewteB .srebmun eht htiw eugra t'nac uoY ?tahw os tuB
,nekops eb tsum ti nehw
,ocitnauQ ni mriF ecnegilletnI hsaWsoB eht esirprus dluow taht noitamrofni fo sliart tuo sterref ehS
-- gnihtemos stih RADIL eht nehw ti evol yehT
taht si hcihw ,txen sneppah tahw yb draug ffo thguac si doowtA ,si ehs sa egde no sa nevE  .syas ehs ",ris ,swen ehT"
,nus eht ni gnikaos ,spets s'ydobemos ssorca slwarps eh sA
-- fo duorp si ehs gnihtemos si sihT
.tac a rof ,hsikar elttil a naht erom dna
,sdnopser ehs nehw oS
yaw fo tros gnitrecnocsid ,gniyfirroh a ni
.t'noW"  ".egnahc thgim tI"
,dlohesuoh orimakA eht ni elbatemit a no si tsafkaerb
.sgniht wen tuoba gnidaer ,elpoep wen gniteem
.sdrow ni nigeb ot evah saedi esoht dna
,sllub bus-C no ruomra ydob tset yeht yhw s'tahT
.goD dooG a eb ot tneiciffus ton si tI
.levag s'egduj a ekil sllaf
-- evitaluceps ylsseldeen ro gnitcartsid ro suoenartxe gnihton s'ereht erus gnikam
;efil yliad rieht gnipacse fo yaw a s'tI
.seod netfo os ti ekil
.skool ti naht redrah si god a fo efil ehT
.pot eht gnola pirts a ni atad noitanitsed dna nigiro htiw dedocne ,spirts cillatem niht ni semoc ti
.taht meht llac nac uoy fi(
,guh a reh sevig neht dna ,ti tae reh stel
.gnol ekat t'nseod tI
htuom ruoy ni tup nac uoy gniht a ton tub
,liam eht teg ot koot ti emit eht gnidulcni ,despale won evah setunim neeteniN
.tecuaf nekorb a ekil noitamrofni war gnipmup
,era sgod tsom ,tceffe dna esuac gnicart ta doog ytterp s'ehS
.tsaf oot semit ytrof nimereht a gniyalp s'ehs ekil skool doowtA
,erew yeht tahw fo esuaceb ton -- neve ,lanimeS
.tey nwod ti nip t'nac ehs tub
.ssenippah sih dnoyeb gnihtemos eb thgim ereht taht neht sesilaer doowtA tub
.scitilop citarcuaerub detacilpmoc fo yraicifeneb eht s'eH
;gnol selballys ytenin tuoba liatkcoc gurd a no pu stac eht poh yehT
.reh tem reven sah doowtA
,sknaht fo wob tneivresbus a sevig ehs nehw dna
.efil fo trap tsuj s'tI"
.tnatsissa lanosrep ni-evil sih si rehtien dna
swap reh htiw noitamrofni fo secruos eht setalupinam ehs ,sekil ehs sgniht sdnif ehs sA
-- roinuJ ,gniK rehtuL nitraM dna
.sdnuos namuh tsom ekam nac sgoD