…llew ,no kcab kool nac ew gnihtemos htob meht morf dliub ot
.emit lasraeher - won klat t’nac
,elkcuhc a delfits ehS
,acsilaV ehsA yb
”.moor PIV eht ni stfihs wef a llup em gnittel s’nam dlo os - spit eht ssim yllaer I llew - haeY“
.dik keew a 523 s’tneR“
.ytpme ytterp yllausu saw nur siht ,hcaoc eht evael sregnessap eht fo tsal eht gnihctaw suG derewsna ”,puY“
”.enod erew ew gnikniht saw I
.bojtun a sa delebal uoy dah
“ – ecalp siht ,tsuj I“
.niorg dna hcamots siht ta bur ot nwod gnihcaer dnah eerf siH
,detrons regit ehT
.slennut fo krowten evisnapxe eht dnuora delttuhs dna sebut latem ynit otni dehsams efil fo sklaw lla ;syawla sa dedworc saw liar nwot ssorc ehT
.elpoep yrtsudni eht lla – rotcerid
.dnuora teg ot droffa dluoc eh yaw ylno eht saw ti won
.ecnatsid eht otni ffo gnikool seye pu
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”,tfel eht no rood driht - llah eht nwoD“ ”.si ti erehw wonk uoy“ ,mih rednu morf tuo mra sih llup nayR gnittel
”.ynneP tsuj esaelP .ynneP“ “– ma’am uoy knahT“
– sfeirb rexob sih fo tuo gnippets dna strohs sih nwod gnihsup erofeb mrof ehtil sih gnihcterts daeh sih revo pu trihs sih dellup knumpihc ehT .partskcoj
.renroc eht dednuor ehs sa roolf eht tsniaga dekcilc enac reh ,nilognap dega na detnurg
.gab sih morf emac prihc teiuq A .”…diputs“
.tsehc s’nayR tsniaga ylerauqs daeh sih fo kcab eht desserp dna srepmihw drahciR
.sniats retaw dna retsalp krowhctap eht gnirucsbo llaw eht no nrettap wodahs nevow a gnitaerc gniliec eht sdrawot pu deb siht yb pmal eht no edahs eht denrut drahciR
pu doots eh sepirts sih gniniltuo stnecca revlis eht htiw tnetnoC
”.repeed ni ti evird - hcaoc
dna hguoc llams a tuo tel eh
,ssa nrow llew s’drahciR tsniaga doow gninrom sih gnidnirg drawrof desserp eH
.koob tseug derae-god a tuo gnikat
,drawa emos gnidloh drapoel eht rehS lenoiL ot txen
.epoh dna sehsiw llew
,seires llams a hguorht deppilf eh ”,ytuop ooT“
,rihS lenoiL taht moor emas eht ni gniyats m’I ,noitpac eht gniddA
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
- hsalf a yb dewollof dekcilc dna
.ecneuqes yrtlus a ni
.dik ti htrow toN !hE“ ”!ni
.emarf regral dna remraw s’regit eht tsniaga kcab desserp drahciR
derrihw aremac ehT
.slanimodba sih fo gnillor peed eht ot
– enomiS dna ht54 .rotcudnoc eht fo llac pots delbrag eht yb dewollof
.wam sih otni rehtruf kcoj eht gnihsup dna
,txet dennac llams a gnidnes
.”…retfa eerf - myg eht tA“
”,05 dda euqehc dna tiderc tnuocsid a uoy steg hsaC
5002 gnirpS  * * *  ”.od I woN“
gnirih erew uoy dias dna drac ruoy em evag enoemos - mmmu - iH“
4002 llaF  ”.sselwalf#
”.htnom eht rof dnarg neve na ;laed a uoy tuc ll’I .dik ereht pots tsuJ“
,sllib fo elip llams a revo dednah dna tellaw sih otni dehcaer eH ”;ynneP sknahT“
.daeh sih otni kcab dellor seye sih
”.gninrom s’ti - kciD“
,tsurht dilos eno ni drawrof spih sih devom
regit ehT .mih rednu gniyal knumpihc eht fo sredluohs eht dnuora depparw sregnif kciht siH
.snoitacifiton sih no pu wohs sesnopser wef eht dehctaw eh sa ecaf sih revo daerps elims A !devirrA tsuJ
srekcits dna sehctap esactius pu-taeb elgnis a tas hcaoc eht ot txeN
– yaw drah eht taht nrael ot dah eh dna
serutcip kciuq a rof elgna na no ti gnidloh ,enohp sih tuo koot eH
”.uoy llac lliw ew tnelat euqinu ruoy htiw enoemos fo deen evah ew fi ;swerdnA .rM - uoy knahT“
.emoh yawbus eht dna steerts niam eht sdrawot yella eht nwod gnidaeh htaerb sih rednu derettum eh ”,ti kcuF“
,htaerb peed a koot eH
* * *  ”.dias uoy ekil dnarg neve na eb dluohs taht“
,stceffe dna sretlif hguorht gnippilf ppa eht no nottub txen eht deppat eH ”.doog skool taht“
elpoep fo sdworc eht hguorht dehsup knumpihc ehT
– tsael tA .rehtegot gnisraeher dna gnignis fo sthgiN
”.krow rof ydaer teg retteb I sseuG“
”?yllanoisacco enifeD“
”.dnah fo tuo oot teg
llaw eht gnola gnitiaw riahc eht morf gab sih derehtag ylitsah eh sa derettum eh ”,yrroS“
.timil raen sti ot dehcterts hcuop eht
ereh dna“ ,ssa denot s’knumpihc eht no ylmrif dnah a gnicalp
moor rekcol eht sdrawot yaw sih gnikam
”.setunim erom eviF“
,drahciR ta niaga devaw eh sa ecaf sih no regna gnisaercnI .tuo dellac eh
.mih ta kcab detuohs suG ”!diK yeH !diK“
,mih ot resolc drahciR dellup dna delbmur regit ehT
elbat elosnoc eht ot moor taerg eht ssorca yaw reh edam ehS
,yb og sraey eht sa dnA
knip etitep eht gnibbarg
”?ecnavda ni htnom a rof yap I nac ,nac – ma’am seY“
.sserdnus a ni knumpihc ylnortam a fo egami eht yb deinapmocca neercs enohp sih no tnemmoc a dehsalf
spih eht fo gniyaws edis ot edis tfos eht morf gnihctiws denrut dna nups eh sa sehcnert peed gnittuc flac sih ,gel tfel sih denethgit nayR
eb ll’I“ ,desopxe mih gnivael edis eht ot dehsam llits hcuop eht
nwod meht gnihsup strohs llabteksab sih fo dnabtsiaw eht otni sbmuht sih gnikooh
kcoj knip nwo sih fo hcuop hsem eht tsniaga dnah sih debbur drahciR
yltsoM .snoitacifiton dna strela sseltnuoc eht hguorht gnillorcs dna enohp eht gnikcolnu yltfed sregnif siH
”.elgna rehtona morf ti ees ot deen thgiM .onnud I“
.kroY weN ni devirra eh nehw netfo did eh taht kcehc elpmis a saw tI
sih rednu dnuora sdnah sih dehcaer eH
.rekram knip ni moor PIV eht ot txen delwarcs deman sih
.noisseccus dipar ni nekat serutcip lareves
sserttam eht otni ecaf sih gnidnirg revo dellor eh flesmih no pirg sih esol ot ton luferaC
eht lla siht ekat tseb uoy - gnirts tsrif yalp ot tnaw uoY“
htiw hcae serutcip fo seires eht ekat ot kcab eht no nottub eht gnippaT
.daeh s’regit eht ylno ni
srorrim eht ta tops sih koot eh rekcol sih otni gab dna gnihtolc sih gnissoT
.tohs eht fo emarf eht gninethgit dopirt eht detsujda eh
,noitartsnomed fo yaw yB  .edirP htiw
,deksa drahciR ”?ereh ew era – tahW“
.senil bir tniaf eht delaever
neercs potpal sih no nottub tsop eht tih eh
regnarts a ta gnikool neve lleh – gniklat
,rettilg ni derevoc ma I“
eno siht piks esaelp
,tenalPruF rof gnaF fo
.seigolohtna fo rebmun a ot rotubirtnoc dna
,yrotsih yawdaorB fo seceip eht ni koot seye sih moor noitpecer eht otni repeed gnivoM ”?ereh enoyna“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.gnihcaelb-nus dna tsud yb derucsbo eman eht
4002 retniW
.roloc eht fo emos pu gnikcip ecaf sih no rettilg eht
”,em hcuot ot evah yeht od tub ,haeY“
kcoj eht fo hcuop eht drawrof spih sih gnuws eH
tsehc sih tsniaga rethgit gab llams sih dellup ylevitcnitsni drahciR
,redluohs s’drahciR otni gud swalc siH
.hcamots demmirt yltaen sknumpihc eht tsniaga ylthgil wap sih debbur regit ehT
htaerb peed a gnikat
.yawA thgiN eht ecnaD s’ynnaD
,daeh sih koohs dna semit wef a detnurg suG
”,tuortS lyrehC ,senihT teragraM
,snevetS yrneH ,swerdnA drahciR
sthgilhgih eht sa tsugsid ni delknirw eson siH
rotide remrof si ,gnitirw emit elttil oot sdneps ohw ,acsilaV ehsA yb
,enohp sih fo noitarbiv eht tlef eh mroftalp eht gnihcaeR
esaelP“ .ttub dnuor sih tsniaga meht gnippans ,kcoj sih fo sparts eht ta gniwap stel
.peed ni rettilg revlis dna knip eht kcap ot mra sih otni hsurb eht gnidnirg ,delworg drahciR
.peels eht yawa hsurb ot gniyrt seye sih ta debbur eh
.ria rof gnipsag ,detnap drahciR
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.enog saw enoyreve dna ekawa saw enoyreve taht erus ekaM
.wam sih otni hcuop eht devohs
sub ehT 4002 remmuS ylraE  2 fo 1 traP
,semit nwo ruo ni dna yllacirotsih htob ,evah sevil reeuQ
”,arroleV .sM“
”.uoy rof deksa sgnikoob eht fo eno sediseb“ ,redluohs s’drahciR no ylmrif dnah sih gnisserp ,derruhc regit etihw tliub ylkciht a
,ruf nwo sih otni rettilg revlis a gnikrow ,delrans nayR
”.ssip ot deen I dna
riahc sih ni ylthgils delffuhs eH ”?srecnad
.tfel eht ot erom elttil a tsuj - yakO“
,ppa txet eht nepo deppat dna
;gnicnad t’nerew uoy thguoht I“
.dias setisbew dna skoob eht ekil gnihtyna t’nsaw tI .ecalp eht fo kool nwod-nur eht ni koot eh sa depacse hgis detaefed A .eniL s’recnaD
”?tcirtsid ertaeht eht ot ti si yaw hcihw – mmmu ,yeH“ .kcar pot eht morf no-yrrac llams sih debbarg dna deddon knumpihc ehT ”.tsol teg woN
.aidem laicos sih no tsop ot eifles rehtona gnikat gnitabed
gnitirw sih rof tnirptoof latigid eht gniluahrevo yltnerruc si ehsA
.sllibyalp fo seno edamemoh deretsalp dna desolc gnol swohs fo srekcitS
.ruf s’regit eht ot gnilc moor eht fo tsud tneibma eht gnikam ria eht ni gnuh taews fo llems kciht ehT
.ay rof tihs rey teg lliw sretrop – ereh
- yM“ .llah eht pu kcab gnimoc raeh dluoc
,wodniw ytrid eht morf ni delkcirt thgiL
.ruf sih gnittam sregnif sih otni ti gnibbur dna cirbaf eht hguorht erp fo emulov gniworg eht gnidaerps
”?krow retfa snalp yna tog
,tsehc sih ot pu dekcut sdnah dna tuo deffup skeehc sih ,knumpihc a fo emarf llams eht - wor htneves eht ni pu delruc tuB
.kcoc s’nayR dnuora sedisni sih denethgit eh ria rof gnipsag llitS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
deb eht morf pu flesmih dehsup eH
.lriws dna ecnad tsud eht gnikam nus gnisir eht
dna dekrims nayR
.ffo dna nwod partskcoj nwo sih gnikrow dna sgel sih gnikcik deb eht dnuora devom drahciR ”.kcab thgir
ylitsah drahciR sa elkcuhc a flesmih gniwolla rae s’drahciR raen deb eht fo daeh eht ot pu partskcoj nwo sih dessot eH
anirellab terref suomaf eht oksuM aliL fo serutciP
4002 remmuS etaL
.”…gnipoh yllaer saw I selor surohc emos ni sgninepo wef erew ereht draeh I“
eh gnihtemos ,tsaeb yracs a neeb dah yawbus eht nwot ot emoc tsrif dah eh nehW
mih deciton enoyna ssel ehT
”?eromyna hguone ton egarag eht dna gnicnuob
”,ti ekat nac I -- hcaoc seY“ ”.yaw
.hcaoc eht gnieelf tub lla elpoep eht ffo gnitnuoc rorrim eht ni ylesolc dehctaw eH
pu enohp eht dleh eh ydob sih gnitsiwT ”.tsop ot emiT“
”.sruoy fo ssa kcoj taht pu nepo s’tel - haey“
.nepo srood tnorf dna kcab eht decrof dna mra rood eht gnuws eH ”.marcs woN
,sthgit sih gniniats sraeT
,tseretni sih edih ot gniyrt hctorc nwo sih revo dnah sih decalp ylkciuq
srepap sih morf pu kool ot rehtob t’ndid worc ehT
.tsehc sih ot pu dellup seenk sih roolf eht no gnittis llaw eht tsniaga depmuls eh renroc eht dnuora dna llah eht nwod spets wef a gnikaT
yawdaorb# ratsecnad# maerdehtgnivil# yawa lla meht welB !snoitidua dehsinif tsuJ“
liameciov ot enohp eht tnes eh thgir gnipiwS
* * *  ”.yob ytrid a evol od I“
detlit daeh sih ,llaw eht tsniaga kcab denael dna etomer eht pu dekcip eH
redluohs dna daeh sih detfil knumpihc eht gnilbmurg dna gnitnurG
.steerts ytic eht ot sriats eht pu dna
gninediw seye sih ;regit eht ta kool ot daeh sih denrut drahciR
.tellaw rof gnihcaer stnap sih dettap drahciR
.cipot thguarf a neeb sah ytilauxes reeuq dnA .drah neeb
eman s’nayR no gnidnal stcatnoc sih hguorht deppilf eH
.repap fo aes a ni mih gnirevoc drawni llaf ot denetaerht stohsdaeh dna semuser repap fo seliP
.gnithgil dna elgna eht erus ekam ot neercs eht gnikcehc
”.uoy gnideen eb t’now ew - og lla nac uoy“
emos mih gnivig sdraug ytiruces ynam oot eno
”?hcnul rof dnuora uoy nam yeH“
.ssa depparts s’drahciR edisni toor eht ot flesmih evord eh sa denaom nayR ”,…kcuF“ .tegrat sti ecreip rebmem nellows sih gnittel edis eht ot devohs hcuop-kcoj eht fo hsem eht
potpal sih no egami eht gnikcehC
”?sevom eht evah llits I kniht“
.rettiwt sih wollof ot si gnitirw sih dnif ot yaw tseb eht os
.sdraobroolf gniwob dna levelnu eht no gnitfihs seohs sih srood yrtne elbuod ykaeuqs eht hguorht deppets eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
a tsurt hcae htiw drawrof erom tib a tsuj gnihsup
,tsud fo reyal yvaeh a ni detaoc dna ytpme moor nommoc nepo egral eht tuo dellac eh ”,olleH“
* * *  .hcum oot elims ot ton gniyrt
”.siht gniod yllaer I mA“
.mih dniheb ti gnittuhs dna rood eht ot dedaeh dna
tog ew sa esirnus eht ees ot detnaw I !kcuF“
– elbaliava si 7 mooR“
cisum elbiduani emos ot htrof dna kcab gniyaws liat sih ,noitats siht ta taes nwo sih gnikat yawa deretnuas nayR
”.hcaoc yssup kcoj ym kcuF“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
- toG“ .weiv ni tsuj gniraeppa tops tew ynit
.elbat ynit sih morf dekaorc gorf dega ehT
.smoor nommoc ni gnitirw dna gnignis elpoep ,snehctik ytinummoc
”.gnikaeps nomiS - s’ynnaD“
”,yllanoisacco ysdnah gnitteg elpoep dnim t’nod uoy fi doog si yap eht tub ,gnol era sruoh eht oS“ ”.ecnad uoy ees attog tsuJ
seenk sih ot nwod sredluohs sih morf elcsum yreve dna hcae gninifed thgir eht
,sregnis ,srotca ,srecnad fo yb enog sraey morf serutcip
”sfeiraeB dna srexoF“ ni dehsilbup tsrif saw ”yawdaorB dessA eraB“
.neercs eht no sretlif eht htiw delddif knumpihc eht
.ti yojne ot tub ytilauxes reeuq htiw enod eb ot gnihton dna
.taes sih ni elbissop sa llams sa flesmih gnikam
”.snoitidua pu gnidloh er’uoy – swerdnA .rM“
.noitces artsehcro eht ni taes tilkcab sih morf rotcerid eht dellac
”?tnorf eht ees ot tnaw uoy hO“
.knip fo egnit thgils eht gnikat skeehc sih no ruf nat eht ,dehsulf knumpihc ehT
.tnelat wen rof gnikool syawla era eW !sreppuY“ ,gnilbmurg dna srepap fo gniltsur A
t’nseod ti sa gnol sa
nwod gnitnuoc syad eht ssorca dekram kni der ni nwodtnuoc a
.sredluohs sih no gnicnalab mih gnivael deb eht pu ffo kcab sih llup dna naom prahs a tuo tel ot drahciR gnicrof
,neercs eht no esnopser ni deraeppa drow elgnis A ”.rewohs
,parts kcoj ym ot gnikcits
,tsehc sih ni peed delbmur dna delims regit ehT
.taes sih ni gnihcuols drahciR deksa
– emoh ekil t’nsaw tI
.ssendrah lluf sih ot flesmih dekorts eh sa
* * *  .elbissop sa peed sa mih gnillup dna ydob s’knumpihc eht gnihcnurc
nossel taht denrael d’eh retteb eht
moor eht dellif snaom dna stnap tfoS
– enecs ertaeht gib eht ni strats rieht tog yeht elihw evil ot sregnis dna ,srecnad ,srotca rof ecalp A
eh regit eht rof noitativni nepo na htrof dna kcab gnikcilf liat ybbuts siH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,stnemngissa eht ta keep kciuq a gnikat
.sraet dna skcink eht pu gnirevoc
edisni dekcud dna kcol s’rood kcab eht no rebmun edoc sih ni dehcnup eh yella eht nwod gnidaeH
.rood ssecca yella eht tuo dna sepor eht hguorht srehto eht htiw yaw sih gnikam egats eht fo tnorf eht morf gab sih detcelloc dna dehgis drahciR
.raor sih fo dnuos eht htiw moor eht gnillif dna kcab daeh sih gniworht ,nayR delworg
.sserP xoF deruomrA yb
.s’ylluS morf yawa skcolb wef a
”,!eihciR ti od nac uoY“
.enohp sih otni rebmun eht deppat eh ksed eht no drac eht gniyaL
,dnah sih ni revo dna revo drac eht deppilf drahciR
,swodniw etalp egral eht morf ni gnimoc thgil eht ta gniwap snrut dna dessot knumpihc ehT
niadsid dna tseretnisid naht naht rehto gnihtyna htiw
.erutsop dna ,srae ,skeehc ,eson ,seye fo stnemtsujda thgils
.noitaruoloc nairtsedep sih ot ssencitoxe
enohp sih deppirg ylirgna eH
skcart eht tsniaga sekarb eht fo gnidnirg eht draeh eh sa daeh sih tsniaga kcab talf srae sih dekcilf drahciR .ecivda yldneirf
5002 llaF
ruf sih otni peed ti krow ot rettilg dna sehsurb eht rof gnihcaer
.daer eh tahw s’taht
,acsilaV ehsA yb ”yawdaorB dessA eraB“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT      .”P: enod“
.swodahs emos gnidda dna
.ria nabrubus esicerp dna naelc eht ot derapmoc gnimlehwrevo stnecs nabru dna goms fo reyal kciht ehT
regral tib a tsuj ti gnillews ,kcoc sih deslup
,ti ta gnikool ton gab eht ta nwod dewap yltnesba eH
,egats eht ta dnah tfel sih gnivaw yltnesba
,lewot neerg llams a htiw worb sih morf taews eht depiw drahciR
htuom sih ot ti thguorb eh sa gnilbmuf sdnah siH
,ylevissimsid devaw gorf ehT
”.rekcufrehtom eht ecnuob ll’I - uoy hcuot yehT
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
ylduol denaorg knumpihc eht ”,…eroM“
”.gnitsaC ytiuqE ot uoy ekat ot meht llet dna bac a liah tsuj“
er’eW“ ,sregnessap gnilbmurg eht kcab rorrim eht dekcehc dna worb sih morf taews eht depiw ollidamra redlo ehT
,meht evil ot tub sevil reeuq htiw enod eb ot gnihton si ereht ,meht evah ohw su fo esoht rof tuB
,deb eht fo edis raf eht no llaw eht tsniaga depmuls drahciR .hgis peed a sa tuo ti gnittel dna
,ti noitpac ot gnilbmarcs sdneirf sih rof
.seenk sih otni deirc ”,diputs ,diputs ,diputS“
ksed sih no radnelac eht ot dettilf seye siH
”.yadot t’nac tsuj I - mom yrros m’I“
,flesmih deppots eh ”…dik netsiL“
,deraeppa gnipyt fo noitamina llams eht yletaidemmi tsomlA
.rorret reehs morf sregnessap eht ffo devahs ti sraey ynam woh dna kaerb ot dah ti swal ynam woh rettam t’ndid tI
,won tuB .retsam dluow eh thguoht reven
.thginot uoy htiw ereht m’I llew haeY“
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab denettalf srae sih
neht dna tfel eht ot tsrif skcottub denifed sih gnitfil edis ot edis morf spih sih dellor regit ehT .daeh sih fo kcab eht tsniaga rehtegot decal sregnif evissam sih ,daeh sih tsniaga kcab talf srae sih dial regit ehT
”yawdaorB dessA eraB“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.hcuop ffits dna detsurc muc eht ta gnilkcus
der thgirb dehsulf drahciR
segde eht ni gnipporc erom tib a otohp eht detsujda dna dekaewt eH
”,tib a noitarutas eht pord ebyam ,tsartnoc eht pU“
.kool ni tnrub eht ti evig ot segde eht gnirrulb dna
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.rehtegot sdnah sih gnibbur ,eson sih dehctiwt terref eht
.egami tseb eht dnif ot gniyrt serutcip eht hguorht pilf ot nageb drahciR seenk sih no ecnalab ot kcab enohp eht gnilluP
,ngis derehtaew eht ta pu dekool drahciR
”.ti dnif I ecno retal pu yek ruoy gnirb ll’I
noitidua eht morf tnelis no llits
derettum eh ”,mom sknahT“
nayR delworg ”,ym
”,noitnetta eht no evil uoy esaelp hO“
parts kcoj sih revo pu strohs sih dellup eh sa derewsna nayR
.di rellac eht no gniwohs rehtom sih fo egami eht
sseug I naem I“
,gnivaw ,gnilimS .yaw drah eht
.emit-no saw MA53:9 eht – syawla sA
t’nod - ecalp ym“ ,ytaews gnitteg
.ecaf sih otno elims a gnicrof dna sraet sih kcab gnillup ,delffins eH
”.yob ym keew a naht regnol ereh deyats enoyna ecnis emit gnol a neeb s’tI“
.etad eud tner eht litnu
dna elkraps dedeen eht gnidda
;delaeuqs sekarb eht dna derettups enigne
spil sih dekcil knumpihc ehT
tuo reward eht dellup dna
.bruc eht ot tpael dna eno tsal eht gnippiks sriats hcaoc eht nwod debmilc eH
.ttub denifed dna sgel denot sih ffo lairetam xednaps eht gnicrof
”.trops ,strops fo dnik taht otni etiuq er’uoy kniht t’nod I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.drahciR rof erots ni evah tsul dna efil sesseccus elbissop tahw ees ot emit txen ni enuT
dna gut eltneg a gnivig ,sllab tsedom sih ta debbur yldi eH
,deffuhc eh ”,kciD yeH“
.enil nepo eht hguorht eciov gnikcarc a derettihc
”!yob semoc ti ereH“
niart eht gnitixe
delbmurg eh ”…kcuf“
”.detsop siht teg dna skeehc ym ni kcab ruoloc emos tup s’tel os - yakO“
.tuo ti dehguoc yltpmorp dna
”yawdaorB dessA eraB“   :yojne esaelP
parts kcoj der thgirb a laever ot
.drawrof pets esaelp eman ruoy llac I nehW“
dna gnitfil regit eht tuoba gnikniht
.emit no eb ot gniog saw suG
.ecalp emas eht ni enohp sih tpek syawla eh
”.thginot ytud PIV eb ti tel t’nod esaelp“ ,bur
.stnapucco eht gnikahs kcab dna drawrof hcrul ot hcaoc eht desuac pots eht fo ecrof eht