- weiv elttil ddo eht ni koot eh egdirb eht fo gniliar eht no gninaeL
,roolf eht tsniaga ylduol depmuht liat siH
.s’knumpihc eht tsniaga wam sih gnisserp
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.dloc llits ma I dna sraey gnikcuf ruoF“
;llac ytoob yaddim ym teg t’ndid I - oS“
.enohp eht revo knumpihc a fo laeuqs hctip hgih eht emac
drawtuo gnivohs swalc sih toof sih dexaler eh ”,elohssa
.elgnuj nabru eht edisni tserof eht
”?huh suoires gnitteg era JC dna uoY“
,dnah tfel sih htiw pal sih ni koob eht fo segap eht hguorht delbmuf nayR
,yldaorb delims regit ehT
- niaga - noitidua eht no deliab uoy rehtie os
.owt trap ot netsil ot kcab emac lla uoy taht dellirht si ohw
,niorg dalc kcoj sih tsniaga elzzum thgils s’knumpihc eht gnisserp ,rewol ylthgils ecaf s’knumpihc eht gnivom
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
* * *  .ylf s’knumpihc eht pu gnippiz ylluferac
.elims yrw a htiw dias eh
,eniL s’recnaD eht ta kcab dekool drahciR
”.tsrif aedi rehtona dah I tub
.strohs dna trihs elcsum a ,sehtolc remmus sih gniraew llits ,delkcuhc nayR
”,bojwolB“ ”.eno kcip
.ssik eht otni derrup eh ”,uoy evol I“
;thginot nohtaram a gniwohs ertaeht esuoh tra na si ereht ,yllautcA“
.roolf eht ssorca derettacs gnihtolc fo selip llams eht revo deppets eh sa delkcuhc nayR
”.trops aedi taerg a s’taht kniht I“
”.gig eht tog uoy ro
dnuorg eht ffo mih detfil nayR eht erofeb desolc ylerab tnemtrapa s’drahciR ot rood ehT
”!llibyalP eht ni detnirp eman ym evah ot gniog yllautca ma I
”!ttub ym ffo dewohs ti dias uoY“
.no ni hgiew noinu eht fo srebmem lla taht yrogetac eht si siht esuaceB .raey hcae evig ew sdrawa lausunu tsom eht fo eno si drawa sihT
”?ecalp ym ta xes yknik ytriD“ “
.edis eht ot koob eht gnittup ylhsipeehs dias nayR
.sdrawa fo yhtrow wohs siht ekam ot derih neeb evah I“
”,emit erom eno taht raeh I fI
.tnerehoc gnihtemos ot sthguoht sih gnillup delworg eH
,arolflaM aihtnyC
”.mih dellik evah thgim I etunim rehtonA“ ,regdab a tuo deirc
- ebyam llew - seY“
?etarbelec ot gnihtyna gniod uoy era oS“
”.htiw syawla er’uoy regit taht nees ev’I - spih esoht esu nac uoy wonk I“
”.rab eht ta stfihs mooR PIV eht od llits dna slasraeher od dluoc uoy detsisni uoy esuaceb“
.sserP xoF deruomrA yb dehsilbup
.slasraeher ruoh neetruof fo syad thgiarts evlewt morf dehca kcab dna sgel siH
”!tihs ekil skool ti ro NI yats gnikcuf swalc ehT“
,drahciR no detser seye sih ”,kool ehT
hcuop deniarts eht ta elzzun dna pal ot seenk sih ot gnippord nruter ni drahciR delworg
,rae s’drahciR otni gnirepsihw eciov sih derewol dna dekniw nayR
”,yenoh taerg s’tahT“ ”!trap eht tog I“
”.gnihtemos ro knird ot hcum oot dah uoy mih llet
.mih dniheb tuo ti gnidloh xob eht morf azzip fo ecils a depiws eH
.rekihhctih flowerew
,seenk s’nayR no smlap sih desserp dna niaga kcab dellup drahciR
- erom ecno ecaf sih ssorca gnidaerps elims eht
.anosrep gard sih fo eciov ikik sih fo enot prahs eht no gnikat eciov sih - detrats dahC
”,ti od dluoc I dias uoY“
”.rehpargoerohc - yas uoy od woh
”!nohtaram sroirraW mrotS ehT ot stekcit teg uoy did kcuf gnivol-reve eht woH“
- sraey gnikcuf net naem I
,eson eht no nayR ssik ot seot sih no pu flesmih dehsup dna gib delims drahciR
”.sdrawa eht ot teg yeht neht dna su deef yeht - oS“
tsuj dah eh - detnap drahciR
.”- em denaol skoob esoht lla daer yllanif I ecnis dna
.deb eht otni kcab neht dna ria eht otni sgel sih gnikcik deffuhc drahciR
”.gnoht a ni etuc dekool uoy dias osla I“
”!yawdaorB no recnad laer A !nos yM“
”!recnaD lapicnirP“
yojne esaelP  .enoyreve rof
”,trohs elttil a m’I kniht I - on hO“
* * *  ”.won thgir seno-no-eno gniod ylno m’I yrros tub
”.egakcap klat koob dna kcuf eht ot edargpu ro
”!uoy fo duorp os ma I“
.seirogetac dna sdrawa suoirav eht hguorht yaw sih denord kravdraa ehT ”.das
,skcehc depmiks eht ,lleh fo skeew rieht devivrus lla dah yehT
”!hsulb mih ekam ot nrut ym saw tI !noeL“
?thginot ereh yats ot tnaw uoy oD“
”.trops thginot eb ll’I erehw wonk I lleW“ ”.ecnaraeppa na ekam attog - thgin partskcoj
.enif s’ti - mom oN“
erofeb swalc sih gnitcarter ylluferac ylwols nwod gel sih tup amup eht
”yawdaorB dessA eraB“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.sraey neetfif tsap eht revo elyts gnitirw sih no evorpmi ot emit fo tol a dah s’eh ylsuoivbo naem I“
”.noisnetxe liat a raew uoy gnikam t’nsi eh tsael tA“
”!etarbelec ot ihsus ot em ekat ot desimorp eH !hguoht sruoh wef a ni pu em gnikcip s’eH“ ”.wonk uoy llew
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
- neht dna - trats ot klaw a - lleW“
si ohw wonk lliw ew keew eht fo dne eht yB“
,seye sih dellor dna detnurg knumpihc ehT
- doof ;gnivrats m’I
.nwo sih evoba tsuj liat ekaf a ot nwod sparts htiw osrot sih dnuora depparw taht gniggir ssenrah eht evomer ot detrats dna detsiwt eH
”,kcab - deen - tisoped …thgiR“
.nayR ta dehtuom eh ”,ti potS“
,ylteiuq llef sevael ehT
,rae s’drahciR tsniaga tsuj eson sih gnisserp
s’thginot - tfihs tsal eno gnioD“
,ffur keehc sih tsniaga ecin gnileef odexut sih fo lairetam tfos ehT
”…thguoht I hcum os mih tuoba klat tsuj uoY“
”.liat a deen I - recnad suoires a eb ot tnaw I fi tub
.tihsllub tseiceps gnikcuf taht etah I“
drawrof devom sah efil dna
”.trops taert ruoy
.tilps peed a ni daerps sgel sih roolf eht morf pu dekool drahciR
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
redro ni meht od ot evah ll’uoY
.lairetam denepmad eht fo rovalf ygnat-dna-teews prahs eht dna tnecs yksum hcir eht ta ylippah gniredduhs ydob sih
,trihs sih tsniaga swalc s’regit eht
”?rebmemer - mom pu ekorb eW“
7002 gnirpS  ”.oot
- tops eht s’tahT“
”,etamilc wen a ot cnys ot seidob ruo rof sraey net ekil ekat nac ti erehwemos daer I“
,enil eht revo deohce emac feiler fo hgis A
.nayR dneirfyob regit sih htiw
,ecaf sih gnissorc tnemtnioppasid fo hsalf a
eno siht piks esaelp
”.ereh tog I nehw saw ti yaw emas ehT .siht ekil tsuj ti rebmemer ot tnaw I .haN“
”.meht tuoba klat em raeh ot ekil neve t’nseod eh - haN“
- syob noitanigami ruoy esu tsuJ“
- s’tahT“ ,ylwols deknilb nayR ”?yllaeR“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,moor eht dellif mih rof taht esion gniparcs teiuq a gnikam swap desuollac hguor sih egats htooms eht no htrof dna kcab delffuhs drahciR
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
8002 llaF
”.won thgir ni nworg yltsom m’I ereh“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.srae s’drahciR fo htob dniheb gnibbur dewem regit ehT
- bojwolb ro klat kooB“
”.yaw siht ecruos ew taht yrogetac ylno eht si tI
,htrof dna kcab spih sih gnikcor
teef sih ta nwod dekool knumpihc eht
,ytic eht ni devirra nehw saw ti sa emas eht
,terref eht dekrab ”,enoyrevE“ .seton sih gniweiver egats eht fo tnorf eht ta terref eht no dexif seye lla srecnad desiop fo enil eht nwod gnikcehc moor eht dnuora detrad seye siH
ta s’eh deciton t’nevah lla ew kniht t’nod yoB
”.tuo gnihtemos krow nac ew kniht I“
.ylerauqs `euqaJ deye yeht sa sreggad ot gnineprahs srecnad 03 eht fo noisnet evitcelloc eht - denekciht moor eht ni ria ehT ”.gnikcal si“
,ylsuoiruf htrof dna kcab gnikcilf liat ybbuts sih ,rood eht ot decnuob drahciR
”,seires eritne eht ni koob tseb eht ylsuoivbo si sdrowS neveS eht fo ecnaD“
.mi‘ kcuf ,ylsuoireS .mi‘ kcuF“
* * *  ”…tnew sgnoht ym erehw snialpxe tahT“
”?raey tsal tem I eno ehT ?sruoy fo dneirfyob taht htiw tuo gnioG
”?esael ruoy revo ekat I yako s’ti erus uoY“
”.kcoj a ni retteb kool uoY
”- yad nmad yreve tsomla emoh uoy sklaw
”.won siht htiw wohs erawa yreve trats ot evah yeht os desufnoc repus era ohw elpoep emos era ereht yltnerappA“
wap sih werdhtiw ylwols regit ehT
,delkcuhc drahciR
”.drocer fo dnik emos eb ot sah ereh gnivil fo sraey 01
;tsuj I thguoht I - doog hO“
.ni gniworg llits taoc retniw sih
.hcuop-kcoj deniats dna deniarts sih ot yaw sti gnimrow dna stnap sih fo reppiz eht no gniggut walc a fo hcuot etaciled eht tlef eh sa ssalg retaw sih otni derepmihw eH
.gnilkcuhc dna rehto hcae ot gnirepsihw noeL dna dahC ees ot gnitrad seye sih dehsulf knumpihc ehT
”?bojwolb retfa klat kooB“ ”.eciohc doog“
”.pleh rof dneirf a deksa I“
,acsilaV ehsA yb
”.esaelp siht evah em tel tsuj
,sgel sih tuo gnihcterts nageb dna rab pu-mraw eht revo deklaw dahC ”.erom spih ruoy esu ot evah tsuj uoy - liat gnikcuf a tuohtiw ecnad nac uoY
.ratS gnisiR si yrogetac lanif ruo - gnineve eht fo drawa lanif ruo rof dnA“
.sdniw llaf psirc eht ni thguac
trofmoc rof skool ,snoitidua fo dnuor rehtona morf detcejer ,drahciR - yawdaorB dessA eraB no ylsuoiverP
.tilps eht fo enil etaciled eht gnitortnoc dna
”.thgiarts skeew owt rof kcoj siht gniraew neeb ev’I“
,naorg tfos a tuo tel eH
- dehsulf drahciR ”,oot uoy evol I“
.elbat teuqnab eht tas yeht sa nayR eht tsniaga desserp drahciR 8002 gnirpS
6002 remmuS  2 fo 2 traP
.trops ti ekil skool - haeY“
;trops weiv eht gniyojne tsuj - gninialpmoc toN“ ”!pudduhS“
,deffuhc dna regit eht otni denael drahciR
;pu tekcaj sih fo ralloc eht dellup drahciR
,kcirtapkriK relyT
.skcals sih ni eerf gnah ot rebmem gnillews s’knumpihc eht gnisaeler dna
yehT .keew tsal ynapmoc tnemeganam eht htiw ti deraelc I haeY“
”.sdneirf tsuj er’ew …I“
kravdraa demarf-llams ehT
;thginot tnaw uoy gniht devarped revetahw od ot esimorp I“
,peels peed s’regit eht hguorht tuc enigne s’bac a fo erifkcab duol ehT  * * *  ”.gnikcuf neht
eno siht peek nac uoy yob doog a er’uoy fI“
”?bojwolb dna klat koob oS“
.skcoj sih fo hcuop deniats taews eht otni ecaf s’knumpihc eht dnuorg eh sa drahciR revo gnimool ,deffuhc nayR
.devivrus lla evah uoY“
,daeh sih revo pu trihs sih dellup nayR ,xob nepo eht otni kcab azzip eht gnissoT
.5202 erofeb
”.thginot ti teg annog yllaer er’uoy woN“
?ereh ni mraw tib a teg tsuj ti did ro em ti si“
,regdab eht deppans ”,tihslluB“
,drahciR eht ta nwod erats dna tis ot gniliar eht otno pu gnippoh dnuora nups nayR
dneirfyob sih revo mra sih depard regit ehT
,htmraw artxe eht gnideen regnol on ydob sih regit eht morf yawa dellup dna dehsulf drahciR
,riahc deffutsrevo ypmul eht ni revo gnidaer saw eh koob eht morf pu dekool regit ehT
”.edart - ni yap nac I ebyam tub“
”!xob tsal eht s’taht oS“
”.trops ereht thgir kcil
”.swerdnA drahciR dna
,niorg s’nayR ta gnilzzun dna gnippal ylippah drawrof denael dna deddon knumpihc ehT
,acsilaV ehsA yb ”yawdaorB dessA eraB“
.uoy tuoba si yadot tuB
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
- wen ruoy ma I ;xiorC eL `euqaJ si eman ym“
s’tahT“ .egats eht hcuot
:era ratS gnisiR 7002/6002 rof seenimon eht dna“
”,drah os siht si yhW“
”.ereh taht od ot elba eb yltcaxe t’now ew - ereh smoorhtab eht nees ev’I“
”,driew eb ot sah taht uoy yvne t’nod - haeY“
.delbmurg lla srecnad ehT
”.syad eerht ni - nepo eW
”.worromot kcab emoc ton od - tuo era uoy yad eht fo dne eht erofeb tuc era uoy fI
”,meht ot klat em evah syawla nac uoy llew
.duts no ti peeK !yeH“
srae s’drahciR neewteb gnibbur thgir sih
”?htuom ym ni ti t’nsi yhw - taert ym s’ti fI“
.spohc sih dekcil eh sa deniarts sdrow sih detnap eh
s’ereH“ ,muc deird dna taews morf wolley ylthgils deniats kcoj etihw a ecno saw tahw delaever dna nwod stnap sih dehsup eH
”!hsulb mih gnikam er’uoY !pots dahC“
naem I ?emit tsal eno dnuora kool a ekat ot deen“
.sgnirts teppup elbisivni eht no tsellat rieht dnats ot pu dellup lla srecnad fo enil seiceps-itlum eht ecaf ot dnuora nups terref ehT
dnah eerf sih tuo dehcaer nayR
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.kcab dehtuom regit eht ”,em ekaM“
”.toh os tog tsuj ti“ ,knumpihc eht sdrawot pets a koot eh “ - naem I
.ruetama - gnicnad ehT .citehtap - sweiver ehT
dnoces a rof deralf slirtson s’knumpihc ehT
,dnoces a rof ylippah deredduhs knumpihc ehT
,72.23$ eb lliw taht - drahciR rof yrevileD“
,noitapicitna ni gnihsarht liat sih
,ediw delims dna edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc nayR .noeL derrup ”?ssalc eht htiw erahs ot tnaw owt uoy gnihtynA“
yaw taht krow t’nod swalc gnikcuf ym“
,leizarG inahpetS
’!siht ekiL !seot ruoy tnioP‘ ,skeew thgiarts eerht rof ssa ruoy gnidir neeb t’nsah eh tsael tA“
,desolc rood eht dellup dna nav gnivom llams eht otni ti dedaol eh sa ylippah derrup nayR
”?uoy nac meht daer ot ecnaL teg t’nac llitS“
”!dessimsid era uoY !lla si tahT“
,mih tsniaga mih gnillup
.niorg sih ta gnibbur wap suoveihcsim s’regit eht morf mih tcartsid ot gniyrt taes sih fo egde eht no ylevitnetta gninetsil drahciR
;ees ot thgis a s’tahT .ym-ym tuB“
- revo gniyats er’uoY
gnitadimitni eb ot tseb sih gniod tsehc sih tuo deffup regit eht
,llah ytpme eht dellif hgis a mih dniheb tuhs dehctal rood eht sA
,eson sih gnippat regit eht ta pu dekool dna seye sih dellor eH
.nepo-er ot ydaer saw wohs eht won dna
,ecaf s’nayR ssorca daerps nirg hsilived A ”!emosdnah yeH“
modkeeg fo level taht - epoN“
,draobpilc eht tsniaga swalc sih deppat terref ehT
.retpmorpelet a yb detpmorp hguoht sa moor eht hguorht ekorb esualppa fo dnuor llams A
.decitonnu tnew tub
- haey os ro keew tsrif ehT“
.kcuf dluoc ew os ffo meht ekat ot uoy tnaw tsuj I - deil I“
!noitpo wener htiw tcartnoc raey 4 a s’ti oS“
4102 remmuS
,nwod denael nayR
,taews deird fo tnih tsetniaf eht gnihctac
.teews dna tfos neeb gnivah tsuj retfa
”.driew yllaer sgniht ekam ot tog
- od yeht fi dna elbuort yna uoy evig t’now
”.esion sht ssim gnikcuf t’nod I“
,riahc eht fo tuo flesmih hsup ot sgel sih dessorcnu dna delkcuhc nayR
”,enuJ ni taht rebmemer ll’I“
,hcuop hsem deniats taews eht otni repeed ecaf s’kcumpihc eht gnisserp
,sdneirf sih morf yawa denrut ecaf sih peek ot gniyrt yaw eht fo tser eht ssenrah eht fo tuo flesmih deirruh drahciR
,tib a dehsulb nayR
,acsilaV ehsA yb ”yawdaorB dessA eraB“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
,tilps gnidnats tcefrep raen a otni gel sih gnitfil delbmurg amup a
”.tops a dessim uoy kniht I
”.deciton t’nevah ew kniht t’noD .stleb ecnad dna spartskcoj naht rehto gnihtyna gniraew deppots ev’uoy dnA“
.daeh s’drahciR fo pot eht dessik nayR
.nosinu ni derettu yeht ”,uoy knahT“
”.elppaenip dna inoreppep elbuoD“
,nayR ot repsihw ot revo denael drahciR
”.teuqnaB s’recnaD launna eht ot gnimoc rof uoy knahT .enoyreve gnineve dooG“
,sevoorg gnivael gniliaf enots eht tsniaga deknilc swalc s’regit ehT
.duht wolloh a htiw deb sih otno llef drahciR  * * *  ”!secalp gninepO“
.krap eht ni srevir laicifitra ynam eht fo eno revo egdirb eht ot llih eht pu detrats yeht sa meht draeh eno on erus gnikam krap eht dnuora detrad seye siH
,sehtolc sih gnivomer ylitsah dna seohs sih ffo gnikcik ylisub derrup dna nwod mih tes nayR
,elor eht tog eh taht yoj fo laeuqs deticxe na reh gnivig ynneP tsap gniwolb
,sehcnuah sih no gnittis dna kcab gnillup dnah s’nayR tsniaga delggurts drahciR
”,enog s’eh kcuf knaht hO“
9002 llaF  ”.uoy evol I“
,dnes gnittih dna egassem kciuq a tuo gnipyt enohp sih debbarg dna deddon regit ehT
”!slatner era esehT !yeH !yeH“
.ertaeht eht dnuora slennut fo ssem eht otni stixe egats eht sdrawot edam terref eht pets hcae htiw denessel noisnet ehT
”?krap eht ni klaw a rof emoc ot detnaw uoy dna rehtegot ffo yad a evah yllanif uoy oS“
”.pit erofeb
”?gnittiuq er’uoy ylluS dlot uoy evah
”.6002 ni enod krow rof era sdrawa lla - sdrawa fo sepyt eseht ot wen era ohw uoy fo esoht roF“
”,weiveR yawdaorB yaG fo rebmem tsewen eht ta gnikool era uoY“
- won dessap sah raey a revo tuB
senil nevow eht gnola ti gniraet ylluferac ylairetam eht tsniaga walc sih deggard eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,pu mih kcip dluoc ti level a ot nwod enohporcim eht dellup
,eugnot sih dekcilc terref ehT
- emitemos elbissecca dna kcab gnitirw sih teg yllautca ot gniog si eh taht su ot sraews ehsA
tlef eH .sdrow esoht degnahcxe dah yeht emit tsrif eht - ti draeh dah eh emit tsrif eht saw ti
,elkcuhc a tuo tel amup ehT
”-- I fi dam teg lliw ecnaL“ ”?semit dlo ekiL
llac eht ekam ot moor sih ot sriats eht pu nur
.won taht gnildnah tnemssarrabme eht
0102 llaF
”.seohs gniraew etah I .siht rof tuo gnittup os era uoY“
,taorht sih deraelc kravdraa ehT
”,wonk ay sreppop no noog elpoep tsom
”!llits sdneirf taerg era eW
.nmad a gnivig yllautca ton tub euqitirc gnitpecca fo drocer nekorb ehT
.sdneirf tsuj si sraey eerhT .thgiR“
.ni si ohw dna - tuo
.knumpihc eht delbmurg
.liat a fo bun sih gnilggiw wollip sih otni demaercs eh
,tnemssarrabme eht gniyfilpma ecnelis eht - tnemom a rof teiuq tnew enil ehT
,wohs yreve retfa rood egats eht ta uoy rof stiaw ,wohs yreve
.ssecca level retaerg ro dneirfyob rof si
”sfeiraeB dna srexoF“ ni dnuof eb nac sretirw detnelat yb rehto ynam dna ,yrots sihT