.tae ot doof fo stol dna
.ssensuovren lauteprep a htiw nekat hguoht sa
,nesir evah tsum roloc yM
,daorb dna gnol saw liat reH
,gnorw si ecnetnes eht fI
.yella na ni flesym dnuof dna
,nerdlihc sa deyalp dah ew ecno erehw stnorferots dna sesuoh ytpme eht dessap I sA
”!no sehtolc emos tuP ?gniod uoy era tahw ,lriG“
dnuos egnarts a hcus
:noisulcnoc eno ylno saw erehT
”.emoclew er’yeht ,nam daed a golf ot meht sesaelp ti fi
.ti dewollof taht eno eht yb tuo deffuns eb ot ylno
tuo dewolloh neeb dah hcihw
roolf eht otno tsrif-ecaf delwob tsomla I taht
ssel gnihton saw noitanitsed riehT ”.thseheB“
,ecneserp ym dnim ot raeppa ton did eh sA                     ”.flesruoy tiuS“
,dlohserht eht revo deppets dna
.ylleb gnidurtorp s’aidaN rehtar tub
,enog si ytic eht fi tahw tuB“
,efil morf detnaw reve ev’I lla s’tahT
,nrob neve erew su fo yna erofeb
.syaw ynam ni tser eht morf tuo doots erah eht rimA                       renoitucexE ehT
tfahs noitalitnev derettahs A
.ograc eht fo trap emoceb ot ti fo pot no rebmalc neht
,detrats yenruoj ym retfa sruoh erem navarac eht otni nar I .thguoht I os rO
.gnivil a rof ffo sdaeh s’elpoep tuc I“                     ”.ris ,seY .seY“
”thseheB“   si yrots s’yadot dna
,thguoht otni kcab delttes eh
.srae dednuor sih esopxe ot sa noihsaf a hcus ni depparw eno
,tsrif ta tnedicni eht fo kaeps t’ndid I
,hteet sih neeb evah tsum tI
.dneirf deifimmum rieht ekil selom lla erew yeht detseggus noititned riehT
”.tsol saw dnik ruoy thguoht I“ .dias I
”?stnerap ruoy era erehW“
,dirbyh a rof reh koot I emit eht tA
.elcyc taht reilrae dehcraes d’ew esuoh a morf gnitaname wolg a ees dluoc I dna elihw elttil A
,emit ni su fo lla wonk ot emoc ll’uoY“
,ti ni edirp saw erehT
”,aet deredwop elttil a dnuof eW“
,eb thgim taht erehw ot sa deriuqni I nehW ”.retteb raf
.seldeen yrovi tuots htiw denil erew swaj sih ekil
.od ot gniht elbatirahc eht saw ti dna
;nioj ot gnicnivnoc dedeen t’ndah I ,neht tuB
,noitnetta werd tsom hcihw srae rieht ton saw ti tuB
:drow elgnis a dias dna delims eh
,moor tsrif siht ni ymmum rehtona saw erehT
.gnola raf os emoc ot sraey ynam ni tsrif eht si aidaN yM
.seilimaf renoitucexe rehto gnoma yrram ylno nac ew snaem tahT
,demrala tsrif ta ton saw I
setir lairub reporp sniamer eht evig ew taht detsisni rupahS
.ti morf stiftuo eritne rehtegot tup ot meht rof sisao rieht ni nommoc neeb evah tsum hcihw tub
lla fo tsom tuo doots taht gniht eht tuB
”?stius latnemnorivne tuohtiw dnalrevo su hcram uoy lliW
,gniliec eht ta pu dekool ehS
,enil citpo-rebif htiw stnalp eht rof nwod thgilnus gnirb eW“
.noitnetta ot kcab em gniltrats
.ti fo raeh t’ndluow I tub ,tnemelttes taht ni pmac pu gnittes fo klat saw erehT
.sevlesruo dnif ew hcihw ni dlrow eht tcelfer tseb hcihw
,uoy dlot ydaerla I“
,ecafrus eht no neddus a fo saw I
,dne no doots srae dna kcab ym no sriah eht
hgamehs s’kabaB
,neht yb reh htiw pu thguac tsomla ,dias I ”,lleW“
.dne hgih eht sdrawot gnidnet sepytonehp regral fo esoht dna
sniur detsalB“ ,gnitnuat ,cidica
nworb dna wolley fo sedahs delttom
.gnihton htiw emoh emac dna
.dniheb evael ot decrof neeb dah I doof eht dna retaw rof
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,rehtegot kcab klaw ot detrats ew dna
,pu tes dah eh rouqil fo selttob eht lla dnuof dah eh erehw ylbamuserp saw tahT
,esolc yrev era eW
.dednetsid erew seilleb rieht litnu
.deid rehtom erofeb ecnis ,sraey ni draeh ton dah I sa
.elttil os rof doog saw eh nehw dnuora mih luah ot troffe eht ekat dluow ew yhw dnatsrednu ton dluoc I tsrif tA
,lassoloc a llits saw tub
.railucep eb ot sa sdradnats yraropmetnoc morf devomer raf os tub
,esuoh a dehcraes I sA
”.gnol os deyats evah ton dluohs uoY
,pu nworg dah I erehw emoh eht ot kcab
,drocer siht ssorca elbmuts dluohs uoy fI
.rohtua yrots trohs gninniw-drawa dna naicisum
”.riapsed ot uoy gnirb ot tnaem noisulli na ylno saw tI
,emitrennid ta dnA
sreksihw dna eson siH
”.dellik sevlesruoy teg ot gniog era sloof uoY
elpoep tsal eht gnoma eb thgim ew ecnis od ot gniht reporp eht demees tI
.hguoht ,ereh spots tI
.ydaer meht dah slotsip htiw su fo esohT
dluow taht selcihev fo segitsev tneicna eht gnoma ereht
,dnalburcs neeb ecno dah hcihw
,eciov emas eht saw tI
,llat sretem owt revo llew saw ehS
,sisao denodnaba na ssorca emac eW                       nnijD ehT
.suoicsnoc saw esle enoyna fi ees ot dediced I os ,ainmosni htiw elttab a gnisol saw I dna
.daeh rieht denrut dah pmal a gniraew enoemos ekil
.em toohs t’now yeht dias reven I“
,cilobmys saw erutseg siht os ,gnorts ron egral rehtien ma I
deppots I                     ”.noitavlas rof yarp dna
shtuom rieht otni demmaj sedarmoc devrats-flah wen ym
,sesimorp sekam dna spam sih revo serop rupahS
.tnedifnoc ,dias ehs ”,sey ,hO“
.serots rieht fo tsal eht revo gnilbbauqs srebbor yawhgih fo ylimaf a neeb ylniatrec tsomla dah nem eseht taht dedecnoc eh hguoht neve
”.yad lanif eht litnu htrae eht klaw llahs dnik yM“
.eye ym fo renroc eht morf tnemevom thguac I nehT
depparts esproc margolik evif-ytriht siH .emit fo daeha denoihsaf d’I gnils a ni meht deruces neht
,gnol riah sih raew ot elam ylno eht dna
,sesac-wollip fo ezis eht tuoba sgab fo riap a gnihctulc saw eH
,ti noitnem ton did ew hguoht ,deciton evah tsum enoyrevE
,maerd a saw ti rehtehw flesym erus ton saw I ,semit tA
,kcots citeneg elov fo nam trohs a ,redael riehT
,dias eh ”,smsylcatac eht ni tsol saw hcuM“
.sniatnuom eht fo spot eht neve revoc dluoc eH ylerus
.depmacne ew nehw meht htiw ekops netfo I dna
”?meht rof gnikool er’uoy esuaceb
noitcelfni yrotailicnoc a no koot enot sih esuaceb
,ezigolopa I ,rehtorB“
”.gnihtemos uoy evig lliw ew dna em htiw emoC
.doG ni htiaf evah I“
,nees reve dah I ytic tseggib eht raf yb saw tI
,seow sih lla rof tuB
.elihw a peels noitasrevnoc fo daerht eht tel ot tnetnoc erew ew dna
.ekops ew nehw syad owt navarac eht htiw neeb dah I
.gninetsil saw ehs fi erus ton saw I taht os
detniop I .deksa ehs ”?erehW“
.no devom dah klat eht taht dnatsrednu ot ton demees eh tub
,nem fo straeh eht ni si tahw swonk eH ylnO“ .dias eh
”?deripsnart nis tahw neht
,pmup eht htiw moor eht ni noitisop evisnefed a pu koot ew dna klat s’tnemom A
.gnippis yltnalahcnon os saw eh hcihw morf dna
,daeh reh depmub dna deltrats ehs ,su was ehs nehW
erutcurts gnikool-elbadimrof a edistuo ydob tsrif eht dnuof eW                       nemyawhgiH ehT
,su morf yawa raf fi tahW
dednuoser lla ,debmilc I sa sgnid dna semihc eht
.yzarc saw I kniht
.drawer sih ot no tnew abzuR ,oga selcyc owT
,kcab ym ot
,ybraen yrotcaf elbac a eb ot desU
,mih ni AND namuh eht lla rof ,saw
,taht naht repeed raf saw tI
.tnenimmi eb llew dluoc yad taht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,mih rof yarp lliw uoy epoh I
.dne eht ni gnihtyreve
,dabamitaF weN fo tnatibahni tsal eht saw I
.ecalp siht evael tsum uoy ,nos ym
.noitseuq a mih ksa ot neht
.edisni kcab tnew dna ,dias eh ”,hA“
,kcab og ot uoy gnigru ereh gninraw a etirw ot thguoht dah I
”.puorg ruo ot yllamrof uoy emoclew ot detnaw I“
.lemac a saw namow siht dna
.erutinruf yvaeh fo selip htiw dekcolb neeb dah swodniw eht taht derevocsid ew ,yrtne fo snaem etanretla na rof gnilcriC
serawanu os em gnihctac
flesym deleets I sA
,abzuR dnuora elbatrofmoc yleritne reven saw I tub ,em ni AND aobrej eht saw ti kniht I
”,rehtorb ,uoy teem ot doog s’tI
.daor eht fo elddim eht ni gnidnats dlihc aremihc a saw erehT .dnuora denrut I
”?dnuorgrednu seeb peek nac uoY“
”,taht tuoba aedi yna evah t’nod I“
”.asrev eciv dna ,su tuoba togrof yehT
knird rehtona koot eH
,tfel ym ot htap eht otno dnas depmud dah
.gnitiaw dna yawrood eht gnihctaw
,yademos yrots siht etirw dluow I taht thguoht eht dah I
”.esiwrehto ro ylimaf renoitucexe
yrenihcam fo ecnatsissa eht htiw ecudorp ot reisae neeb dah erutcetihcra hcuS
.snisuoc erew yehT
.deremmats I ”,esruoc fo ,seY !hA“
”.nosrep rehtona teem reve dluow I fi erus t’nsaw I“ .derewsna I
,su htiw emoc t’now uoy yhw taht si dnA“
”.gnihton dnuof dna
.ti htiw kcuts tog ohw ,ylbaborp ,lanimirc a saw srotsecna ym fo enO“ .dias eh
”?esidarap si tahW“
.tser sih egdurgeb t’ndid I
.osrot reppu eht ni semit eerht tohs neeb d’eH
.dniheb secalp dehcterw eseht evael dna ,su htiw emoC“ .dias eh
.esoprup sti ot sa suoiruc saw I os ,seirutnec rof raw ni desu neeb ton dah sdrowS
.ecalp siht ni enola ton erew ew taht
.neeb evah thgim nem rehto hguoht
,despalloc t’ndah taht drawtsew lennut a dnif ot gniyrt sraey ruof tneps eH“ .dias I
”?htiaf kcal uoy oD
,dne wol eht sdrawot gnidnet sepytonehp rellams fo esoht htiw
.dednedda kabaB ”,miH ot esiarP“
.flesym eno gnitirw yrt ot emit saw ti denokcer dna
,puorg eht tuoba snoitseuq wef a deksa ehS
”?esidarap ot teg lliw ew eveileb uoy oD“ ,dias I ”,rehtorB“
.dias eh ”,gnilliw doG“
ecnartne kcab eht tuo deppils I
snoitcartnoc citsaps ni delggirw
.epor sa ti desu ew ffuts eht fo hcum os dah ew
.ni meht dnuof uoy xob eht ot meht nruter esaelP
”.nwod tis ,emoC .aidaN si siht dna kabaB m’I .ecaeP“
dabamitaF weN otni kcab gniog pu dedne eW .sreveileb fo
,esac eht revetahw tub
,neeb dah rehtaf ym naht reivaeh saw kcapkcab ehT
.kcor gnivil eht fo
no evom dna pu evig ot devloser tuoba tsuj dah eW
,daeha thgiarts gnikool em
htaerb ym dleh I
.edis hcae no swodniw ytsud dna
?noitavirp ni reffus dna elggurts ot ,dlrow daed siht otni rettil a gnignirb fo
,rotces eritne siht taht esac eht eb yam tI“
,srae ym ni tsenrae dna mraw gnar rethgual eht dna
.tropsnart fo dohtem ruo
:ytiddo na saw abzuR   repeekeeB ehT
.mih rovaf ot su fo wef on denilcni hcihw
.mrif elttil a naht erom tub
,tpurba dna ffits erew stnemevom siH
,evoba pu tresed sselefil eht ekil
.nwod dna pu bob t’ndid waj rewol sih tub
,sokceg tsom ekilnU
.emas eht lla mih gnidule tub
,kcip a gnigniws ekil tsuj s’tI
.senifnoc worran eht ni
”.ereht teg ew ecno ,sediseb elpoep erom dna
.deeps ta denruter erusopmoc ym tub
seirots esoht elcinorhc ot tuo tes evah I
.dias ehs ”,selpoep ruo fo tsal eht era eW“
.drows ym neprahs I
.stfihs ni detubirtsid saw meht gnillup fo robal eht
,ytic yloh eht gnicaf eb dluow
,traeh ym ni epoh fo remmilg a dekraps thguoht ehT
.dexelprep tub ,noitseggus eht ta yrgna t’nsaw I ”?ew dluohs yhW
.em erofeb dnuorg eht no taes a gnikat dna gnilims ,dias eh
hcae dellik neeb d’yeht
”.nwonk-llew os era stibbar hcihw rof gnikab fo tros eht
,mih evigrof t’nod yeht fI
,ekops eh nehw denepo htuom siH .dias eh
dnah sih ni lotsip a dah eH
kcalb dna wolley morf enog dah selacs siH
.emit eno ta ytinummoc gnivirht a neeb evah tsum tI                     .dekoolrevo ro
,noitidepxe siht gnidael nam yloh eht
?taht ekil terces ni tuoba evom ot hsiw enoyna dluohs yhw
,dehgual eh taht tA
enot detum a gnas edalb devruc eht
.nips ot nageb em dnuora dlrow eht dna
,kciuq dna thgil neeb evah dluohs spetstoof ym os
.ytiretsop ot segap eseht timmoc I
.eb ot thguo s’aobreJ a sa
.tsal ta dias ehs ”,ereh yats lla dluohs uoY“
”,lemac a ees ot desirprus saw I“
naelc dekcip erew seitilacol hcus tsoM
”?erofeb dah ti sa
.detutitsnocer dah elims sih niaga meht denepo eh nehw dna
.rimA tem I ereht dna
.emit gnol a rof hguorht neeb dah eno on yas ot efas saw ti
”,ti delliw sah doG“ .delims dna
.sdrow sih yb decnivnoc eb dluoc enoyna woh ees ton did dna
.doof dennac fo lluf
,noitseuq eht dootsrednu eh taht woN
,hsiw s’rehtaf ym fo etips ni tuB
.sdrow wef a naht erom dias ylerar ehs tub ,laidroc tsom saw aidaN
kcarc a saw ereht ,tey
seitissecen eht yb dettimrep ylno ,erutluc ruo ni oobat saw siht sa
.serutcurts deirubnu eht fo tsal eht no
.nwonk reve dah I gnihtyreve revoc ,emit trohs a ni
”,egamirglip eht tpmetta ot enil ruo fo tsal eht saw rehtaf s’rehtafdnarg-taerg yM“
,krad eht ni enola lla gniyd
,nabrut a dna ,ti revo ebor a htiw trihs htgnel-eenk a ,tsap semit ni
.mih morf gnitanigiro naht rehtar ecived gnidrocer a morf deyalp gnieb erew yeht hguoht sa ,ffo tub
”?legna na neeb evah ti thgiM“
,ssecca ecafrus morf ffo tuc eb ot erew eh fi gnol evil t’ndluow eh taht
,libadrA fo sniur eht woleb
,niks ym fo tuo depmuj tuoba tsuj I                     ”?riS“
,lakcaj a delbmeser tsom ehS
?gnileef taht ebircsed I nac woH
.krad eht otni ffo gnirats
,tsuj si ecnetnes a fi dnA
,teop a ,elawD yb
.meht pots ot yrt thgim I hcum revewoh
,tfard a fo egassap wols eht ylno draeh tub
deretlehs evah tsum dna ,sotohp ni neve
,drow a tuo hcraes ot ereh desuap eh ”…daerb eht
,metsys lennut siht ni ereh detalosi era ohw
.teprac ym erahs ot reh detivni I
,ti denoitnem reve eno on hguoht ,dootsrednu lla eW
”,uoy drawer doG yaM
”!peed sretem ytriht deirub
dlrow eht fi tahW
.meht fo ynam ton erew ereht ,hcus sA
,lliw os dluohs ,miH ot esiarp ,doG fI“
”?ti si ,ksa ot hcum oot ton s’tI
.esimed s’wollef siht fo esuac eht ot sa tbuod elttil tfel trihs sih fo kcab eht ni seloh ehT
.raf siht ti edam ew woh swonk ylno doG
,nairatilitu saw eh gnisserd nI
yawrood eht sdrawot devom thgil eht nehT
,talf srae ,deksa eh
,sserts rednu si eod a nehW“
?detniat I ma ,neht ,woH
etsap tneirtun dlo-raey-ytfif fo ebut a no gnikcus mih dnuof I
erew yeht sa slenap eht tfel I ,oS
,dewollof neeb t’ndah I erus eb ot em dniheb keep ot saw noitcaer tsrif yM
,seye sih ta erats ot ton drah saw tI
dekcatta erew eW“
,raf siht daer uoy fI
,noitanigami ym ylno saw ti taht flesym ecnivnoc ot detnaw I                     .gnihtoN
,elov gniyerg eht fo thguoht I ”.rupahS eveileb uoY“ ”.navarac
retaw fo ytnelp htiw ecalp ydahs ,mraw a s’ti ,em roF“
.gnilttesnu erom neve ezag sih edam slipup lacitrev ehT
,flesmih desucxe dna denway eh ,taht htiW
.draeh sa hcum sa tlef saw taht elbmur a
dluow yeht diarfa saw I
,ecafrus eht gnissecca ebut a raen tnew ew revenehW
,noitcerid ym ni elttob eht deppit eh ,delttes tahT
,htuoy ym ni neve ecalp teiuq a neeb dah draveluob ehT
.dedaeh saw siht erehw gniees tub
moor rehtona ni kaeps ot tnew rupahS dna ehs sa
.efil ot dekraps sthgil daehrevo eht ,revewoh ,siht ni degagne elihW
.efil sti fo dne eht raen si ti naem tsum llems hsa dna ekoms ehT
,yraew meht fo lla
.sraey ynam rof tsal dluohs yeht ,ria yrd ,looc siht htiW
.htap live na ot elpoep fo tseb eht neve evird nac noitarepseD
.puorg a htiw m’I“
.daeh sih fo edis eht ni dnuow a dna
.ti sdrawot devom dna
.depmacne ew revenehw segnirf eht thguos syawla dna
”,dab os ton si krow ehT“
elcyc eno hcram ruo gnirud em ni dedifnoc kabaB
.ydaerla krow sti gniod eb ot demees rouqil ehT
,no gniog saw taht elihW
.meht rof emas eht neeb evah dluoc ti
.delims dna niaga daeh reh koohs ehS
,skoob ni erofeb nees ylno dah I sa ffuts enif hcus
.enola etiuq saw I taht raf os tuo daerps dah snoinapmoc ym taht erawa emaceb I
”.noitanitsed ruoy hcaer reven lliw uoY“
,thgils morf devired aremihc rof dna yb edam neeb dah sgnidliub dna slennut eseht tuB
navarac s’ylimaf reh dekcatta dah stidnab taht
.sepytonehp dna serutluc fo tnemtrossa na detcelfer ecnaraeppa esohw slaudividni fo lufdnah a
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
;nommocnu ton saw hcihw
.ti fo yhs tsuj saw gniliec eht
.deirrac ehs snettik eht ot gnirrefer ,dias I tahw saw
.nevaeH fo trap a deredisnoc si
steerts eht no dnuos eno ylno saw erehT
.dnas eht ni mih deirub dna
,roolf eht no tsud fo reyal peed-sretemitnec-ruof eht yb gnigduJ
,navarac ruo ni strac owt erew erehT .ayibmaj a fo
”.sknaht ,oN“                     .gnireffo
,thgir era uoy tuB
.rebif larutan on
,gnola em netsah thgim slenap ralos eht gnihsams thguoht I
,taorht sih ni lla decudorp erew edam eh sdnuos eht fi sa saw tI
.ecalp sih ekat ot ni deppets I nehw
,ecaeP“                     .ti rof evom on edam ehs tub tsiaw reh ta lotsip a saw erehT
.dnas gnitfihs fo ssih tniaf eht dna
.teef dna sdnah ym fo sdap eht no dloc erew sgnur ehT
”…taht otni teg uoy did woH .hO“
.esidarap ni evirra lliw ew taht emoceb I niatrec erom eht
.eman ym deksa neve eh erofeb meht nioj dluohs I taht dereffo
.nworb hsiyerg a ot
,meht dniheb no tnew tahw
.llup ot nugeb dah I
flesym enigami ot deirt I
,slluks eht gnitnuoc yb devlovni erew elpoep ynam woh nrecsid ylno dluoc ew taht
.hcaer rieht dnoyeb retaw eht dna
.knuks a fo taht ekil
,od su evah uoy dluow tahw tuB“ .dias eh
dehcaorcne yllanif dah senud ehT
?era ereht kniht uoy od esoht fo ynam woH
,thseheB hcaer ton yam uoY
sdrow reh ,dias ehs
?dnaletsaw a etavacxe ot tsoc eht reffus sredistuo dluow yhW .ffo tuc erew eW
.sraey eht revo stnemom eldi ni em ot derrucco dah noiton ehT
.sraey gninnaps tcejorp fo tros evisnetni-robal
,rupahS deman nam a saw redael riehT   namygrelC ehT
,tnecsed ym edam dna
dlrow siht no neeb ydaerla dah ohw eno morf deussi ti hguoht sa tub
.liaf tuohtiw ,trapa sdnoces evif ro ruof emos decaps
.em rof gnikool emoc srelevart wollef ym fo eno saw ti thguoht tub
?aes nosiop eht lias ot pihs a su dliub uoy lliW
?seye nwo ruo htiw ti nees evah ew erofeb erom on era secalp yloh siH
,srehto eht htiw enod dah I sa
,wonk uoy ,citisarap era stidnaB
.tuo gnidaerps neeb d’eh teprac egral eht otno em dellup tub lla dna dnah ym koot eH
,esor nus eht ecno yfimmum ylkciuq dluow hcihw
,srae yknal sih fo egassap eht timda ot ti ni tuc stils dah
.ecnaraeppa reh edam regnarts eht erofeb gnol tiaw ot evah ton did eW
deddon dna delims srehto
sevaeL eht ni nwoD ecaF noitcelloc yrteop stI
.degnahc dah hceeps reh ni gnihtemoS
,deklaw I rehtruf eht tuB
kcab dedlof sreh tpek aidaN
,eno on gnirehtob ,teiuq dna
.traeh reh revo dnah reh depsalc neht
”.enog llA .oot ,srehto ehT .oga gnoL“
.yrots siht derahs I erofeb dessap keew A
.deid eh yad eht sa tcatni esiwrehto tub delevirhs saw ohw ,elom siht
.ecnelis no deredrob ti won
.dnuorgrednu serutarepmet looc eht ni ytivitca lacisyhp deniatsus rof elitper a hcum oot llits
peels ot og ot mih dlot dah I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.taht naem t’ndid I
,gnihctiwt tnatsnoc dna seye yraw sih htiw
.worram eht tcartxe ot nepo dekcarc neeb dah dna
emit emos rof rewsna t’ndid eH
yaw a hcus ni derettacs erew hcihw
,weivretni ot em rof reh tnes evah thgim rupahS
taht derongi ehS
”,ecnatneper erecnis ni miH ot nrut ew fi nis yna evigrof nac doG“
.mutnemom ssecxe eht lla htiw
.htaehs rehtael sti fo eerf deparcs pit eht sa
,tohsrae ni saw enoyna fi ees ot dnuora kool a dah I os
,ytniop erew tub ,elbaezis ton erew hcihw
.daeh sih fo pot eht dessik dna
.evig dluow ti fi ees ot rood eht tsniaga redluohs ym worht ot dediced I nehw
.meht yolpme ot kniht netfo ton did abzuR taht ,neht ,ytip eht eroM
,kcab enog evah yeht dluoC
.yaw siht ni daed eht yrub ot noitidart ruo saw ti tub
.mrof s’dlihc a ni“
.ti od t’ndluoc I dediced dna
.snoinapmoc ym morf raf oot yarts ot ton erac koot I tub
,eldnah ot reisae erofereht dna yklub ssel tub
.detsuahxe erew retaeh elbatrop sih no seirettab eht dna
’,ew‘ gniyas peek uoY“
.epytonehp reh yfitnedi
.ecaep ,uoy nopu dnA“
?ris ,od ot naem uoy od tahw ,oS
,esac eht erew taht fi neve tuB
eveileb ew dluohs tuB
”!em teg emoC !yalp s’teL“
,moor rehto eht ni deneppah dah ti detacidni roolf eht no sniatS
sreyarp dias neht
.enoemos dnuof I litnu pots t’ndid I dna ,dluoc I sa tsaf sa yawa nar I tub ,siht rof em etareb yam ohw ynam era erehT
,neht ecaf ym ni gnihtemos daer evah tsum eH
.dias ehs ”,hsatA m’I ,iH“
,dewollof hcihw noitasrevnoc eht ot yvirp ton saw I
.did rupahS taht desirprus saw I
,taht dna yaw siht srae ym denrut dna
,nwo ruo ekil puorg a neeb evah yam tI
,em erofeb demool yawhgih dnuorgrednu eht fo wam eht dna retal elihw A
wollaws dluow dnaS
.htrae siht klaw reve lliw ohw
.eerht erew ereht hcihw fo
.gnikool neeb dah I hcihw rof rewsna eht em evag dna dehgual eh nehT
,gnituohs ton ,dias eh ”!rehtorB“ “
.yaw rehtie eid ot gniog er’uoy ,si tcaf eht tub
saw ti gniyas dnoyeb yfitnedi ton dluoc I lairetam gniremmihs emos morf edam lla
,erauqs cilbup ro krap a otni eseht eno morf degreme ew nehW
,llaw eht ot kcab sih htiw gnittis
.erofeb seye nwo ym htiw ycnangerp a nees reven dah I
?slabinnaC ?sreredruM“
,ytpme won saw reilrae deipucco neeb dah hcihw gab gnipeels a taht esnes eht dah I
krad eht morf tuo gnireep erew seye fo sdnasuoht hguoht sa
,emoneg namuh eht no desab gnieb ,saremihC
,esidarap hcaer dluow ew thguoht eh fi mih deksa I
.retaeh a fo dia eht tuohtiw doof tsegid neve ton dluoc eH
.ynapmoc nwo sih derreferp eh taht rehtar tub
.fracs a htaeneb neddih dna
.rihsmahs a deirrac eh taht saw
.noitisop siht otni nrob em evah ot tif was doG“
.elttirb emoceb dna sraey eht htiw dedarged dah tub
daeh sih erus ekam ot ssapmoc ym dekcehc I ,evoba pU
.livic eb ot flesym gnicrof ,dias I
,serutaerc gniworrub
,slennut eseht ni snoitcurtsbo tnevmucric nac ew esuaceb tub ,suoregnad si tI
.won meht egduj ot tif si eH ylno dna
.ytsedom reh tcetorp ot nrecnoc a morf sa tnemssarrabme morf hcum sa
.niatrec eb t’ndluoc I tub
.tpmetta eht ekam reven uoy fi t’now yletinifed uoy tub
.sknaht ym evah uoy
.deggurhs eH ”.snug evah yehT“
.dne no doots ydob ym no riah yreve dna kcab ym pu nar llihc A
,tros tahw ,elpoep ynam woh
,stsohg gnisahc erew su fo htob ehT
laem ruo gnirud em dehcaorppa eH
,derotser eb dluoc rewop eht ylno fi retaw fo ylppus ruo ffo pot thgim ew deveileb eW
.eid ot ereh ni flesmih deggard dah eh hcihw retfa
emos fo tub ,erbmit fo eussi na t’nsaw tI
,ylimaerd deksa eH
.taoc gniyerg a htiw elov a
”.efil fo dnik taht rof dereenigne yllaiceps erew seeb ruo dnA
,su fo hcae ot yenoh fo owt ro lufnoops a tuo delod eh
.epytonehp nailitper a htiw aremihc a
ytic yloh eht ni bmot eht taht sdloh noitidarT“ .deunitnoc eh os
.esae ta em tup ot detnaw dna mrala ym desnes yeht taht neeb evah yam tI
.won emit yna ti dnif lliw ew kniht I
.ekoms dna hsa fo dellems dna dekan saw ehS
.dnah sti ni lotsip a htiw enorp gniyal eno siht
,yrrac ton dluoc ew tahW
,did lla ew sa ,wenk ehS
.dlihc a ylno saw ehs nehw stnerap reh dellik dna
,teehs a ni meht depparw dna sniamer sih desnaelc I ,deid rehtaf nehW                       ”thseheB“     elawD yb ”thseheB“:yojne esaelP   .ytiniffA ruF no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
navarac eht htiw gnilevart retfa ,oS
,gnola yaw ruo gnileef ot demotsucca emoceb ew
,nwo ym morf os ro sretemolik derdnuh-eerht ylno
,sniatnuom nretsew eht raen seirotirret rof lausunu ton saw hcihw trihs htgnel-elkna eht
!sreredrum rof ycrem geb I
enoemos gnitatipaced
.syad rof ecafrus eht no evivrus nac ew ,sciteneg ruo dna“
.elims a htiw os did eh ,deunitnoc eh nehW
”.hcum os nees evah tsum uoY“
.deid ehs thguoht evah thgim I ,nwod gniyl neeb dah ehs fi taht
,tleb ym no ayibmaj eht ot nwod derednaw dnah yM
.doG rof ysae os eb dluow ti dna
.detatiga enot sih
,puorg eht htiw elcyc tsrif ym fo dne eht ta
,wen saw ti nehw ksat eht rof hguone digir neeb evah tsum hcihw lairetam etisopmoc emos fo bals a htiw derrab neeb dah rood ehT
”.nerdlihc ruo fo ekas eht rof
.drows sih gnitacidni
.daed gnol erew swollef reh taht
,taht tuoba tbuod ni t’nerew eW
,laem ruo gnikat dna depmacne erew ew nehw
,evaw dnah a htiw eritta reh detacidni ehs ”,eseht htiW“
.seye sih neeb evah dluoc ti rO
.yroeht a evah I ,taht tuoba tuB“
”?dreh a evah uoy od
,drows siht ekil tsuj m’I
,ria etaciled a htiw tcejbus eht gnignahc ,dias kabaB
elbareponi pmup eht dnif ot ylno nwot otni gnilbboh
won oS                     .su rof dna
.nwod daeh reh htiw moor eht deretne ehS
.noitidnoc doog ni pmup a dah taht iaresnavarac a nopu dekcul eW                       damoN ehT
.ebut ssecca ecafrus eht fo reddal leets ytsud eht pu bmilc gnol eht edam I
.ekops eh txen nehw
.was I tahw fo niatrec saw I tub
.uoy dewohs ti noisiv eht ot dnim on yaP
,tnemom a rof seye sih tuhs eH
,sdaor rojam eht dekcehc evah dluow eH“
.nem ni htiaf ssel evah I
,wonk uoY .seY“ ”?gnikaB“
,ayibmaj ym htaehser ot erac gnikaT .niatrec saw I
,dluow dna metsys noitalitnev dlo eht hguorht ni yaw sti dekrow tI
.nepo t’ndluow hcihw ,gnidliub enots eht fo rood eht ni seloh-tellub erew erehT
.sgniteerg degnahcxe dna em ot emac ehs taht
,erom ro sretemolik derdnuh a nihtiw nosrep ylno eht gnieb ot esnopser suovren a
,tsap semit ni eciffo tnemnrevog ro knab a neeb evah tsum taht
,yawbus yreve fo wonk eh dluoc tub
.ecaep ,uoy nopu dnA“
”.derewsna syawla si ereht edam reyarp a taht wonk osla tsum uoy nehT“
.meht rof lennahc a ylno saw htuom eht dna
sdamon tresed fo noihsaf elpmis eht ni desserd eH
.ecapslwarc a gnilaever ,roolf eht fo eceip a pu deirp dah eh ,ni rehtruF                     .mih dewollof I
.seilppus rof egnevacs ot tuo naf dna
”.egnevacs ew nehw raf egnar ot elba era ew
’.ylimaf renoitucexe‘ na emaceb enil lacigolaeneg sih ,no neht morF
.dehgual dna ,dias eh ”,mih eveileb ton t’nod I“
.erom ro seilimaf derdnuh-owt
.smra ruo deretsloh ew dna kool a su evag eH
.mih ot noitseuq eht tup neht
.taorht ym deraelc I
,hcraes ew erom eht tub ,egnarts s’tI
”?I t’ndluohs yhw ,lleW“
,degnahc gnidliub eht edisni thgil ehT
.dehgual dna ,dias ehs ”,oN“
,ecno ta erehwyreve morf gniussi sdrow reh
.edisni ytivitca lairetcab morf pu nellows dah snac eht yaw eht gniton litnu
,yrots siht fo sesoprup eht rof elam sa redneg sih emussa llahs eW
,htiw pu emac dna
”.su htiw knird tsum uoY“ .dias eh
,teef ym no srellor dah I ekil saw tI
.seirailixua eht otni decrof erew ew os
”!em deracs uoy ,doG yB“
,ecnelis yramotsuc reh otni kcab despal ehs nehw dleheb ehs tahw dna
saw taoc reh tub ,denob-enif dna keels
,tonnac llits ,ton dluoc I esuaceb ”dlihc aremihc“ yas I
.detrats teg em tel reven eh tub ,nageb I ”…oS“
.seitirohtua eht no sllaf gnorw taht neht
.yas mih draeh reve dah I naht erom dias ydaerla dah eH ”?noitapucco“
”.duoroD weN“ ti demialcorp egde eht ta ngis eht
.gnicnetnes on snaem taht ,eromyna struoc oN
.mrah yna em delliw reven eh wonk I ecnis riafnu saw hcihw
”,ti otni nrob er’uoY“
.rehtegot delbbarcs dah rehtafdnarg-taerg ym taht
”.repeekeeb a erew uoy raeh I“
etum gniniamer ,deddon I
emoc dluow navarac etarepsed emos denigami I litnu
…reverof gnivael saw I dna
.daor eht otni ,yawyella eht fo tuo
ecalupop a detsaob dah ew nehw
aera laitnediser eht etacol ot saw esnopser etaidemmi ruo
”.gnikab …era I dna efiw ym yhw“
,em dnuora nar dna
si gniog era ew erehW
drawer eht si hcihw nedrag neddih eht
.dah I naht erom tol a saw hcihw
llits os tnew ehS
.sdileye lanoitcnuf sessessop yteirav ”drapoel“ eht
,elawD yb ”thseheB“ saw sihT
.reh retfa deklaw dna ecneitap rof deyarp I
htiw dedne sregnif sih taht tcaf eht yb depleh saw siht fo enoN
.slenap ralos eht rof enod eb dluoc gnihtyna fi ees dna ssecca ecafrus a etacol ot edam ew os
,saw siht reveohw no pu peerc naht rehtar os ,elpoep no yps ot thgir t’nsaw ti taht dlot neeb syawla d’I
,gnirevoc daeh fo tros yna raew t’ndid ohw ytrap ruo ni elam ylno eht saw eH
,dias ehs ”…uoy wohs ll’I“
,sraey erom dna derdnuh a
.dias ehs ”,enog er’yehT“
.selop eht ot resolc srovivrus niatsus tey thgim
.stbuod evah uoY“ ,dedda eh
.pu ti gnikam saw I thguoht yeht wenk I tub
,bwaht etihw a erow eH
,srebmem sti gniweivretni dna
,erofeb sraey emos ni-evac a dereffus dah
”,gnirednow era uoY“
”.eunitnoc uoy fi htaed ylno dnif lliw uoY .ereh yatS“
.puorg ruo ni tsellat eht raf yb
.tsol si yaw eht naem t’nseod taht tub ,yaw a dnif ton dluoc eH
.lluks sih ot noitroporp ni eguh erew hcihw
.repsihw a ot tsomla nwod deppord eciov sih
tsud dedoba won tub erafhguoroht rojam a neeb dah ecno tahw
”,suoicarg oot er’uoY“
:nosrep ym htiw etanigiro ton did hcihw
.srae ruo htiw gniees
.peelsa nellaf dah eh kniht ot nageb I dna
”.ereht ti ekam lliw ew tub ,ysae eb ton lliw tI .spam evah eW
neddih neeb evah thgim sgniht emos ecnahc a syawla saw ereht tub
”,ecaeP“ .ecnelis dna
,gnihtyna yas dluoc I erofeb esuaceb
.neht dna won rebbor a hctac dluow sklof ,eb ot desU
.enod saw I litnu ecaf evissap a htiw denetsil eH .yrots elohw eht
.dehsinav dah ehS
,denialpxe dah rupahS ,abzuR roop tuB
,emag elttil reh egludni ot gnilliw dna
.ssendas fo egniwt a laecnoc ton dluoc ehs tub
.nus fo kcal eht saw ti kniht eW
,sisao emas eht morf erew aidaN dna kabaB
.yaw eht gnikcolb
elcyc txen eht fo gninnigeb eht ta neht
.wolf ot nageb sraet
.nur ot pmup eht gnitteg ni tsissa ot denommus saw I elihw
.mih fo tnorf ni tuo dehcterts sgel
,seloh eht yb egduj oT
.deksa I ”?ereht s’ohW“
,sezis fo egnar namuh eht fo stimil eht nihtiw llef
.sdne eht no stfut htiw ,lerriuqs dnuorg a fo esoht delbmeser erom srae reh dna
,ksab dna edispot og ot troffe eht ekam syawla dluow eh
,ton ro nnijd ,lrig taht fo thguoht netfo I
?lla ta gnidne t’nsi
tniop siht ot pu gniwollof neeb d’ew lennut tisnart niam ehT
.erofeb tnemom a neeb dah I sa
.tresed fo esnapxe sseldne eht no nwod gninihs srats fo edutitlum eht
sserP lesaeW morf elbaliava si
.esu s’esle enoemos rof tnemurtsni na
.snoitaluclac eht demrofrep ehs sa gnivom spil reh
,dias elpoep ,ot nekops nehw edur saw eh taht t’nsaw tI
,nepo gnuws rood eht dna
”?taht saw nehw dnA“
,flesti nevaeH naht
ytic yloh eht ot og ot naem uoY .od I esruoc fO“
si ohw yas ot thgir eht sah nam oN
,aera tnorf taht morf raf ton dnuof ew meht fo tsal ehT
,htaenrednu sresuort htiw ebor dedooh ,etihw ,gnol a erow ehS
,rennam ni elpmis saw eh tuB
.ylper on ot ,gniteerg a tuo dellac I
,skram etib htiw derevoc erew senob eht taht
,enigami nac uoy naht rehtraf neeb evah eW
dlihc a rof reh gnikat llits tub ,kcat ni egnahc reh yb delttesnu ,dias I ”,hA“
,tcnitsid erew sdrow ehT
,yrram ot em rof eno oN
.sselehtenon ecap ym denekciuq I tub
”?neht ,su gninioj eb uoy lliW“
,drow luftcat a dnif ot gniyrt ,thguoht ni ffo deliart I
,daraF“ ,erew sdrow tsal s’rehtaF
,seilppus gniluah nrut laremehpe sih dehsinif tsuj dah eH
edalb eht ekil swalc :skooh laturb
.gnihton uoy sevig nevo ehT .snruter“
,yrotsih lanosrep fo srettam llams no elihw a rof deklat eW
,strihs revollup yggab dna skcals gnirovaf
,ecalp cilbup a ni efink eht desopxe reve d’I emit tsrif eht saw tI
.dnas gnillaf fo ssih eht
.pmal ym htiw enoyna ekaw ot gnitnaw ton
.gnileef elbignatni
,strac eht fo eno gnillup nrut trohs a ekat llits dluow abzuR
.od ot retteb gnihton dah I
.denetfos gniraeb sih dna
”.rihsmahs ym tuoba wonk ot tnaw uoY“
.nrecsid t’ndluoc I ,tahw fo hguoht
.daeh reh koohs ehS
,yldetseretninu deunitnoc ehs tub ,reh derewsna I
,mih deifimmum dah ria looc dna ssenyrd ehT
,emit a saw ereht reve fI .esnefed-fles fo
syad ym fo tser eht tuo nips ot detpmet saw I
”.noitanitsed ruo wonk t’nod uoy tub“
,elcyc taht retal litnu ton saw tI
”,rehtorb ym ,ecaeP“
.selcitra s’rehtaf ym morf kni dna repap pu derehtag I
.detcepxe dah I naht resolc saw hcihw ,htuos eht ot
.yks eht hcuot ot demees taht sgnidliub htiw seitic taerg eht
,dnabsuh reh ekiL
”.reverof ti srednerrus em no dnah a stup ohw eno ehT .yrt meht teL“
,ti tmaerd evah tsum I dias emoS
.ssol a sa ffo nettirw erew ,ti fo strap ro
.gnorw neeb evah dluow s’nam a ekil saw eciov reh yas oT
,nemodba gniglub s’aidaN ot revo gnirednow tpek seye yM
”?esidarap ot ti ekam lliw ew eveileb ylurt uoy oD
”?ti hcaer nac ew kniht uoy nehT“
.elims reh nruter flesym ekam t’ndluoc I
,rewsna na rof taht htiw deifsitas eb ton dluoc I ,esruoc fo tuB
.noitseuq a t’nsaw tI
tuo deruop dna navarac eht fo tnorf eht raen
”.noos meht htiw pu hctac ll’I erus m’I tub ,detarapes emaceb dna
no deunitnoc dlrow eht
.gniog ti tog uoy ecno dab os ton saw trac ehT
,noiger ruo ni taeh lahtel dna dnas lla ,dlrow ecafrus ehT
.noitcerid ni ylno dereffid dna
.navarac eht dnuora yaw sti edam tI
.ecnedive ni saw ,strapretnuoc deggel-ruof reh fo taht ot derapmoc decuder hguoht ,pmuh suomaf eht
,ytisoiruc ym ta dedneffo mees t’ndid eH
,neht nevE ”.ees I“
”,ecaeP“ .em deteerg eH
ssalg no ssalg fo knilc eht draeh I retal tnemom a dna
.tseb eht rof saw taht spahreP
”,egufer ruoy si ereH“
,dlrowrevo eht decarg ecno dah taht noitazilivic eht tuoba thguoht I ”.hA“
,taebtraeh dna htaerb ym ,stroffe yM
.naelc eye sih dekcil dna ,dias eh ”,eyA“
.deyonna ydaerla saw I dna gniteem ruo otni sdnoces eerhT
,draeh dah I eciov s’dlihc a saw tI
,daeh sih koohs dna delims eH
.erif morf edam nnijd erew os ,yalc morf edam erew ew sa nevE
?sehtolc on uoy evah ,gniht rooP
.mraf yna sa emas
.snoitnetni elbon naht ssel htiw snosrep neeb evah osla thgim ti neht tub
smraf tcesni dna scinopordyh eht yb deniatsus
”.dlrow eht ni boj tseisae
.tcejbus eht egnahc ot ydaer saw I ,neht yB
.ecalp ni dexif deniamer I elihw em htaeneb nups htrae eht dna
,daor siht no nur niaga reven
.reh deitip I dna
.no deef ot meht rof eno on s’ereht won tub
,es rep ,neddibrof ton saw hcihw
,lliw ew ,nac ew fI“
.daeh sih no hgamehs etihw nialp a dna
,dias dna delims eH
skoob sih ni htuoy ym devil dah I
,)srae eht gnitnuoc ton( llat sretemitnec ythgie dna derdnuh-eno revo tsuj saw eH
.dekcap ydaerla erew seilppus ym erehw
.dnah ym otni ydnac hcaep a decrof eh retfa dias I
”.suoethgir eht rof renroc eht dnuora tsuj syawla si esidaraP“
,senob htiw dellif tip wollahs a dnuof ew sniamer sih ot raeN
.tcejorp siht ecnemmoc ot tnedurp ti tlef I tub
,dnah yb enod lla saw ti erehw syad eht ni kcab neeb dah ti naht
.ereht tuo gnihton s’ereht
taht tuoba deticxe erew eW
”.setisarap on ,tsoh oN
,noitanigami ym ylno saw ti flesym dlot I
.selyts lanoitidart gniwehcse
.ezis sih rof lufrewop dna ykcots tub ,em naht rellat tib a ylno saw eH
.ssensuoicsnoc ym fo egde eht ta derrits esaenu eugav emos erom eht
elpuoc gnimrahc a erew yehT
.aet htiw pu dedne llits dna ,semit evif desufer I
.htaed htiw gnitrilf saw hcihw
,solik 06 ot esolc ta thgiew sih sseug dluow I
.ycnemelc tnarg ot meht geb dna ylimaf deveirgga eht ot og I ,erofeb elcyc ehT“ .dias eh
.lufhctaw dna raelc erew ,hguoht ,seye reH
”.ytic yloh eht hcaer reve ll’ew fi ,slennut eseht epacse reve ll’ew kniht uoy fi gniksa m’I
.wol gninnur era seilppus eht ,siht etirw I sA
.dias lemac-ehs eht ”,ecaeP“
.etavirp ni mih htiw kaeps ot ecnahc a tog I taht skeew owt navarac eht htiw neeb dah I litnu t’nsaw tI
enola slaem sih koot eh
.dnuora kcits ot dediced I
”.kniht I ,oga sraey net tuobA“
***   ”?sdnah ruo no tis
:hcaorppa ot nosrep drah a saw rimA tuB
.nerdlihc evah ,gnilliw doG ,dna deirram teG
,noitairbeni sih fo tnuocca no evitaklat erom eb dluow dna
,emorhc ekil gnimaelg noitseuq lanif sih ni ynori eht
.enola meht fo lla
.noziroh ot noziroh morf ,dnas ylnO“
;ssenerawa niatrec a swotseb dnuorgrednu efil s’eno lla tsomla gniviL
.su htiw gnola tuo gniyd era yeht mees dluow tI
,nwot tsohg eht ni gnidnats saw I dna revo kcab dellor dlrow eht nehT
.seilimaf ruo ,snwotemoh ruo
;gnorts snosrep ytnewt
.edispot saw I elihw levohs eht htiw yarra ralos ylno eht gnihsams fo thguoht I
.shtped sti otni gnihsinav thgilhsalf ym fo maeb eht
”.thseheB fo yhtrow ton si ro
.taht ta ti tfel ew dna deffocs eH
,yad eht gnirud neve
.navarac siht denioj ew yhw s’tahT
.esirprus ni dnuora delrihw dna
,dias elov eht ”,nnijd a saw tahT“
.daeh eht fo kcab eht ot tohs a htiw
.dias rupahS ”,retsis
.did I tsael ta rO
”.elihw a rof ti tuoba knihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
-dnas eht fi tahw
derednow semitemos I
gnirats ym deciton ehS
?ees t’ndid I taht os swodniw eht rednu kcud ot erac gnikat
,sniamer sih brutsid ot elpoep ro slamina on erew erehT
kniht ehs dluoc woH
”?tbuod on ,siht draeh evah uoY
,ssenllits elbaroxeni ,esnemmi taht ni
”.tuo sdnif eh fi deppihw uoy evah lliw rupahS ?yzarc uoy erA“
.rehtie em deveileb evah t’ndluow I sseug I
.emoc dah emit taht ,thguoht I
,sfitom eniv gnilarips ,etacirtni htiw detnirp sehtolc thgirb ni eot ot daeh depard stibbar erew aidaN dna kabaB   sdewylweN ehT
.nwot fo egde eht tsap lennut eht ni pu tes ot deerga dna detneler rupahS litnu no delbbab I
,ti dewollof dna llaw eht dnuof I
doirep gnipeels ruo saw tI
,gnikniht saw I tahw yas t’ndid I ”.ees I“
?epip ro lennut ssecca