?yekralam taht eveileb uoy nac woN
hcir gnitteg t’nia ew esuaC
sgniht retteB yalpsid
rednirg eht rof taem erom dnA elbissop t’nera sgniht retteB  …gnis lla ew dnA
yaw on s’ereht gniyas peek yehT
ecivda gnivig fo derit m’I dnA
rednirg eht rof taem erom dnA elbissop t’nera sgniht retteB
”elbissoP erA sgnihT retteB“ saw sihT
ew emit yreve dnA
emag eht yalp ot ecirp eht s’ti tuB emahs ’niyrc a s’taht wonk’Y
…gnis attog lla eW  hctib
efil ym lla ti draeh ev’I dnA
.nwo sih fo seirots emos
esruoc fo ,raeh I lla dnA
ecnad dna gnos dlo emas eht teg eW
ecirp a evah t’ndluohs efil tuB
yb teg t’nac uoy fi dnA
esrow ’nitteg era sgnihT
.egap yrruFoS sih no dnuof eb nac smeop sih fo eroM
eid ot emit ruoy tsuj s’ti ,lleW
seil hguorht nees evah I tuB
,relevart wollef ruoy
yawa ekat uoy gniht eno s’ereht fi tuB
seirt enoemos taht emit yreve tuB
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
.seirots setirw dna semag sekam ohw
emag eht yalp ot ecirp eht s’ti tuB emahs ’niyrc a s’taht wonk’Y
citsaisuhtne siht morF
lleh ekil thgif ot evah annog er’eW rednirg eht
…gnis lla ew dnA  ecnahc a
ouq sutats eht evig oT
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
eid ot emit ruoy tsuj s’ti ,lleW
,”elbissoP erA sgnihT retteB“   yojne esaelP
.moc.irikenen.www no
.teop eht yb daeR
rednirg eht rof taem erom dnA elbissop t’nera sgniht retteB
seil eht ot ecnalab emos gnirb oT
yb teg t’nac uoy fi dnA
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
dlog fo sllih esoht fo gniraeH
efirts ni evil ot nrob er’ew tahT
etirw ot emit sekam eh
seye gnuoy yraew eseht htiW
eb ot desoppus s’ti yaw eht si siht taht sI
kaerb nac ew dnA elbissop era
eid ot emit ruoy tsuj s’ti ,lleW
,floWcaM boR si sihT
mrywkooB irikeneN yb meop a
dlo yllaer nettog s’tI
yb teg t’nac uoy fi dnA
yas a tnaw ew emit yrevE
llenk tnereffid a gnir yllanif oT
,skoob daeR-oT fo draoh sih morf gnidaer ton s’eh nehW