dna reed ron woc rehtien ma I ,deednI“
”.wons dna niar eht tuo tiaw ro yzoc dna mraw peels ot hcihw ni ned on evah ot“
.tsafkaerb gnilliwnu na fo hcraes ni sdeew rellat eht otni kcab deppils dna
.elkcuhc gnitaludnu dna gnol a htiw kcab daeh sih gniworht
.yks eht ni duolc yreve ot edis nedlog a dna
,nees evah tsum uoy taht ereh morf yawa raf secalp tuoba erom raeh ot ekil dluow I“
,tnuh nwo reh ot gninruter erofeb gninrom doog a mih dib ot ylpmis htuom reh nepo did ehs yllanif nehW
,noom gnittes eht ta tuo dekool ehS
,sessarg wodaem teews detcelloc nexiv eht
,emit siht lla gnidnetta neeb dah ehs hcihw ot dnuos gnihcnurc eht fo ecruos eht ta dekool nexiv dlo ehT
”.em gnitivni era uoy yhw em llet uoy fi ylno tub“
,tnemevom fo ecnagele dna ecarg hcus nees erofeb reven dah ehs taht llew sa timda ot dah ehs tub
.dehtuom nepo mih ta derats ehs dna
,sessarg eht fo tuo dekop eson prahs a
,sgniltsur dniw dna swodahs gniklats yldetraeh-flah gninrom eht gnidneps retfa dna
.dedne ytiralimis eht ereht tuB
.reh ot demees ti os ro ,xof a fo ssenkeels dna ecarg eht lla dah
.ria eht elpmas retteb ot slirtson eguh gniralf dna sessarg eht morf elzzum etihw tnagele sti gnitfil ,deltrats erutaerc ehT
,gnitae reed dna swoc eht nees dah ehs tahw yb seciohc reh gnidiuG
.erofeb nees reve evah I yna deecxe taht dnim eht edausrep ro eye eht kcirt ot srewop evah uoy ylniatreC
.neesnu otrehtih dlrow a otni dna
,retfos dna retrohs erew sessarg eht erehw
.mrof esroh lufrewop sih ni detisiv dah eh
elpoep nwo ym fo hceeps eht ni eman yM“
yas ot tahw gniredisnoc ,esroh eht ta kcab derats nexiv dlo ehT
.esoohc ot ylno evah uoY“
,dias ehs elims dehtoot-etihw htiW
dednuor teef llams stI
,ria eht hguorht yltneg tpews hsurb ylloow nwo reh sa daorb sa liat a ,ssarg eht nwod dewehc ti sA
,”snoziroH enadnuM dnoyeB“ saw sihT
.seot fo ngis ro swalc on ees dluoc ehs dna
,dnop eht gnidnuorrus aera eht otni htworg wodaem rellat eht morf eson prahs reh dekop assyraN tsal ta nehW
,sgel dnih sih no pu deraer eh taht htiW
,ecneirepxe fo tol a dah assyraN
.eciov hcir sih ni
”?gnorw I saW“ .dereffo eh ”,mrof siht htiw elbatrofmoc erom leef thgim uoy thguoht I“
ssarg eht ni ylbatrofmoc gniyl ydaerla saw eh ,gnimoorg ytniad nwo reh dehsinif ehs nehW
.dnuorg eht tsniaga sevooh yvaeh sih rof gninetsil
,daeha gninnur wodahs gnol reh eniltuo dna
.wodaem reh fo edis raf eht no erutsap decnef a ni syad rieht tneps yllamron ohw swoc dettops eht fo eno dnif ot detcepxe ylluf ehs
esroh a yllaer saw ohw xof nedlog ehT
,sevooh evah dna ssarg eht tae uoy hguohT
,”snoziroH enadnuM dnoyeB“
dna taoc der yksud nwo reh htiw deniwtne ruf yklis sih
,raeppasid dluow eh thguoht nexiv eht sa tsuj ,neht dna
,gnitatiseh tuohtiW .gnitiaw
.fooh dednuor eno fo noisserpmi eht yal ereht reh erofeb ssarg eht ni tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.taorht sih ni peed dnuos gnilkcuhc a edam esroh ehT
,assyraN detanimulli smaeb gnitnals sti ,tser sti ekat ot noziroh eht dehcaorppa bro eht sA
”.ti rof stsafkaerb ruo fo rehtie tpurretni ton lliw I tub
.retcarahc ni lasan wohemos tey peed eciov a ni ,dias eh ”,xoF“
.nwad erofeb tsuj thgil flah eht ni denekawa ehs esuaceb ,ecarbme mraw sih ni dezod evah tsum ehS
.tsafkaerb sih eunitnoc dna reh ta kniw ot yticadua eht dah yllautca eH
.gnirewsna erofeb der llol eugnot reh tel dna deknilb assyraN
.orevO ovitlA yb
assyraN ni noitapicitna na reggirt ot demees esuap siH
”.gnitiaw eb lliw I dna
.renoos ecneserp sti fo reh desivda t'ndah eson nwo reh taht desirprus ton saw ehs ,erutaerc eht fo dniwpu gnieB
,liat reh fo hsurb eht no dna ruf reh ni wed saw erehT
.siht ekil gnihtyna nees reven yletinifed dah ehs tuB
.mih dniheb delevel liat yffulf yleguh sih dna nus gnidaf
”.gninrom siht tem uoy esroh emas eht llits ma I .thgil eht dna dnim eht fo kcirt a tsuJ
,noisserped eht ni gnirehtag saw wed gninrom eht taht dezilaer ehs
.otna'anaH ot pu hctac ot gnicar
,orevO ovitlA ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
.noom gnisir eht fo thgil eht yb reh gnihctaw dna
.od ot dah ehs tahw wenk dna
.erutsap rieht ni gnisword swoc eht tsap ,dnop eht tsap
.niaga reh ta kool ot daeh sih desiar esroh eht sa
eht fo syar eht yb detanimulli taoc der dlog ,swap fo tnagele tsom eht no dehcaorppa eh sa
,tnirpfooh eht ta deffins dna kcen reh dehcterts assyraN
,ynihs dna keels ,thgilyad eht ni nedlog dewolg tsaeb eht fo ydob dna daeh eht tub
yaw reh dekrep erew srae tevlev kcalb s'regnarts ehT
rehto hcae decar meht fo owt eht erofeb
”.sevooh ym fo dnuos eht htiw ereh morf yerp ruoy dehsulf ev'I diarfa m'I
noziroh eht drawot drah gnipollag
gniyas mih derebmemer ehS .reh tuoba delruc ydob sih fo htmraw eht
,hguone yletilop reppus rieht tuoba tes yeht suhT
hsub yrrebredle na fo edahs eht ni nwod flesreh dial assyraN
,naeco eht fo dlot
.ti ot txen yletaidemmi sdleif eht dna wodaem siht dnoyeb dlrow eht otni derutnev reven evah I taht ssefnoc I
,liat reh fo pihw yrgna na htiw delworg ehs ”,nexiv diputS“
.meht sserppus ot thguof ehs tub ,dnim reh dessorc skcihc tneluccus dna sgge hserf fo snoisiV
.tros emos fo namahs a dna relevart a htob eb ot uoy eviecrep I“
.gniwehc fael suoicarov naht rehto gnihtemos detseggus taht mhtyhr tnetsisnoc a
noziroh eht revo
.swap reh revo ekiltac liat reh gnilruc dna sehcnuah reh no gnittis ,mih decaf nexiv ehT
.od dluow yeht depoh ehS
.yawyna eugnot reh revo delbmut rewsna eht sa neve yas ot tahw gnirednow ,deknilb nexiv ehT
,gninrom taht tsuj draeh dah ehs taht eciov peed a ni ,deksa eh ”?etal I mA“
”.seimene ym nurtuo I sa niar dna dniw eht nurtuo nac I“ .dias eh
”...tey dnA .dnuos emas eht htiw sevael eht hguorht swolb dniw ehT
.ylthgils daeh sih koohs xof god eht tub ,flesreh morf yawa ti gnigdun
,ezeerb eht ni gnimaerts enam dna liaT
.eye reh fo renroc eht morf elcatceps suourgnocni siht dehctaw assyraN elihw
.flesmih rohtua eht yb
,wodaem reh revo nar ehs
.ecnaraeppa lufecarg s'esroh eht htiw nekat os saw ehs esuaceb ,ezicitirc ot gnihtemos dnif ot dah ehS
.ti tuoba tnecs s'esroh eht fo tnih a tsuj gnihctac
,deunitnoc ehs sa deddon esroh ehT
.yromem s'assyraN ni enod dah lareves dna ,od thgim woc a sa ,dnop eht raen sessarg teews eht no yldednim-elgnis gnizarg saw tI
,deffins nexiv eht
.tsew eht ni gnittes saw noom eht dna
gninnirg dna srae reh gnikrep ,ti no ecaf tseb eht tup ot deganam llits ehs ,desulpnoN
?emoc ot reh deksa ton eh dah ,reh rof tiaw dluow eh yleruS
.tsaf sa etiuq t'nsaw ehs taht timda ot tnaw t'ndid ehs esuaceb ti detcejer tub
gnieb tneitnes yreve ni doog rof laitnetop si ereht taht
.erutsiom htiw ti gnillif
”.reed ron woc rehtien era uoy tey
tra dna seirots sih dnif nac uoY
.mih erussaer ot emit ni eugnot reh dnuof assyraN
.daeh s'assyraN evoba hgih ria eht ni ylfeirb sevooh tnorf sih gnivaw
,evil ot ecalp wen a rof tuo tes ot egaruoc hguone rehtag ot thguo yllaer ehs rehtehw gnirednow dna ecnetsixe evitanigaminu ,enadnum reh gnirednop saw ehs elihW
.deye-ediw ezorf dna
.naeco eht raen detsen ylbamuserp dna devil ohw sdribretaw eht fo seirc eht dna
.dednetni ehs tahw lla ta ton erew tuo emac taht sdrow eht
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.lesnuoc sti tpek ti ,woleb sgnineppah eht fo noinipo yna dah ti fi dna
,noom eht drawot gnipollag ,sevooh krad no flesreh dehcnual yrc gnirevihs gnol a htiw tub
.yllaer gnihton si ti“ ,derewsna tseug reh ”,hO“
,rotisiv eht fo lavirra eht detiawa xof eht ,ylevitnetta dekcirp sraE
,ecnaraeppa ni tfos sa ylraen dna htrae gnirps sa krad ,eye elgnis a taht os denrut daeh taerg eht ,tnecsed drawssarg sti ni gnitlaH
”,ecnetsixe fo tros ycnahc a smees tahT“ ”.nus mraw dna ssarg si ereht erehwyna si emoh ym dna
,reh ot txen yal eh tsal tA
.yletilop srae sih gninettalf ,dias eh
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.eert yrreblum eritne na gnimusnoc ylisub srallipretac dnasuoht dnasuoht a fo esion eht ekil
.ytinmelos htiw reh dedrager
,flesmih fo lluf rehtar saw eh thguoht ehs ,lufhturt eb oT
”snoziroH enadnuM dnoyeB“
.uoy wonk ton od I tey ma I ohw wonk uoy rof ,em fo retteb eht evah uoY“
,niatnoc ylerab dluoc ehs taht
.laem detpurretni sih emuser ot elzzum sih derewol
”.ti tuoba gnihtyna od yllautca reven uoy tub ,sraey rof taht gnikniht neeb ev'uoY“
reppus yratilos a tae dna pu evig ot tuoba saw dna ,gnihton draeh ehS
flesti thgil eht ni ecnereffid a eb tsum ylerus tahw ,sdnuos tnereffid ,llems tnereffid a fo aedi eht saw tI
”.yletelpmoc os epahs ruoy egnahc nac uoy woh em llet yarP
,dnif ot ysae si tI
,gnihtemos no noitatirri reh tuo ekat ot tsuj swap kcab reh htiw htrae eht gniffucS
,ton evah setsat ym ,yliraropmet degnahc sah ecnaraeppa ym hguohT“
.meht woleb sllih eht fo ria eht ni selppir edam taeh remmus eht elihw neve
.esroh nedlog eht fo lavirra eht gnitiawa
,ssarg fo nialp nepo taerg a nO
elov gnitcepsusnu emos gniklats fo sthguoht eldi htiw ssarg remmus llat eht otni tuo deppils xof eht
,dnuos siht ni ecnereffid a saw ereht tub ,esruoc fo ,erofeb srallipretac draeh dah nexiv ehT
.ti gnitcepxe t'nsaw tsuj I
sa onimA yrruF ro ,lysaeW
,thgir reh yb tes elpmaxe eht dewollof rae tfel s'assyraN nooS
,gnikniht eht gniod saw reh nihtiw fles rehto taht esuaceb spahrep ro ,gniod saw ehs tahw gnikniht tuohtiW
,noitnetta reh werd taht dnuos gnihcnurc tnetsisrep tub eltneg a saw tI
,ssarg eht no gnidils sevooh raer ,deppots eH
,enog saw xof nedlog ehT
.erofeb nees reven dah ehs gnihtemos saw ti ,daetsnI
.gniteem tsal rieht ta dereffo dah eh tnemesuma ytsehc emas eht htiw ,delkcuhc xof nedlog ehT
,epir etiuq ton selppa llams fo kcats a
.hguoht ,gnihtemos yas ot thguo ehs taht ,nosaer emos rof ,tlef assyraN
.taerht gnireffo tuohtiw evitnetta seye dna tseretni wohs ot desiar hsurb
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,orevO ovitlA yb
)elam a saw eh taht ylraelc ees won dluoc ehs rof(
.tseug reh rof sdoof elbategev fo kcats detceles yllufthguoht a dna
.sgniw dekcal ohw eno ni deeps hcum os enola tel
,deeps sih no esroh eht gnitnemilpmoc deredisnoc ehS
.edecer ot demees reh htaeneb ssarg eht dna ,ydob reh koohs sniap gnibborhT
.ytirailimaf fo esnes gniworg a emac edutilpma desaercni eht htiw dna ,reduol werg tI
seveileb ylnrobbuts ohw esroh a si ovitlA
.mrotsrednuht remmus a naht reduol dnuos a htiw enilerohs eht fo skcor eht nopu dehsarc dna ,dnop railimaf reh fo sretaw eht ekilnu
,noitategev ro drib naht rehtar tsaeb a saw ti ylraelc rof ,tsaeb sihT
,ssenrednels dna roloc ni nwo reh delbmeser sgel dna teef krad ehT
,gnihtemos tuoba sdnim owt fo netfo saw ehs wenk nexiv ehT
dias eh ”,desseug uoy sa dlrow eht fo strap ynam ot neeb evah I dna
,flesreh rof selov taf fo ecarb a tuo dial yltaen dah ehS
.ksud erofeb tsuj ,lliw uoy fi ned ym ot emoC“
,ytiniffAruF ta
rednu nozamA ro sdaerdooG ta dna "ovitlA"
,ned reh ot ecnartne eht ni tas assyraN
.gnorw ton erew uoy ,oN“
,egde s'dlrow eht woleb pils ot nageb nus eht sa tsuJ
.syad ynam rof niar ot deliaf sah ti sselnu neerg si ssarg eht ,tew dna looc si retaw ehT
.ylthgit noitnetta reh dleh taht
.deyerp ti hcihw nopu sedalb ssarg eht fo rohci eht yb neerg deniats hteet erauqs dna sgninil knip gnilaever ,drawpu denrut pil stI
uoy rof daer dna nettirw
uoy rof daer eb lliw hcihw
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
esroh nedlog eht nioj ot depollag eram yab doolb eht
.gniksa flesreh draeh ehs ”?tesnus tuoba ,gnineve siht yas ,taert llams a rof em nioj ot erac uoy dluoW“
.dnuos eht fo ecruos eht drawot srewolf dna ssarg eht hguorht yltnelis knuls dna
drocca nwo sti fo devom ti woh
,tnirps a ni ffo koot eh sa gniylf stovid tnes teef dnih sih fo kcik evissam A
,yks eht ssorca pirt lausu sti edam nus ehT
.wodaem eht fo weiv gnol yna derucsbo taht seltsiht dna seisiad eht gnoma ffo erehwemos ,esion tnatsid a no desucof htob sa
.yks eht hguorht scra emas eht ekam nus eht dna noom eht ,dellevart evah I reverehW“
.shtaerb tsal reh gnihtaerb eb thgim ehs thguoht ehs stnemom feirb wef a rof dna ,reh nihtiw dehcnerw traeh reH
.dnim lacitylana tnellecxe na dna ,yromem prahs a
.rovaf ot yllaicepse demees swoc eht taht spucrettub dna seisiad dliw emos dna
.dnop eht ni noitcelfer s'nus eht sa thgirb
.drow eno eht tsuj ,derutnev ehs ”,olleH“
.reh drawot kcab gnicar dna nrut prahs a gnikam
,potllih a no gnidnats mih was ehs
.noziroh nretsae eht evoba naps s'liat a tsuj dednepsus noom lluf eht ta tniop ot elzzum sih denrut
”.lavirra ym fo noitapicitna ni eraf lufthgiled emos dedivorp dah uoy ees I dna
,tnemom eht rof gnitnuh fo thguoht lla edisa tup xof eht ,ytlevon yna nopu ezies ot ydaeR
.leviws dna pu dnats rae thgir reh edam dnuos ddo na
si yrots s’yadot dna
”.efil ym decnef evah taht snoziroh worran eseht dnoyeb seil tahw fo gnihtemos em lleT
,otna'anaH si
,ria aes eht fo tnecs eht ebircsed ot deirt eh nehw detnahcne ylralucitrap saw ehS
.ssarg eht hguorht teef nevolc taerg gniggard woc ylniagnu na t'nsaw tI
wons htiw etihw eb dluoc spot rieht woh dna ,erew sniatnuom tahw denialpxe eH
.derewsna ehs ,ecnerefed ni derewol sraE
.delbmur eh ”,uoy dnif em pleh lliw eson yM“
.eye reh thguac ssarg llat eht ni tnemevom thgils a nehw
eciwt liat hsurb reh deggaw xof dlo eht ,yas ro od ot esle tahw gniwonk toN
,esroH dellac ma I .yadot erofeb em nees reven evah uoy os ecnatsid taerg a emoc evah I
.yllaer ,tib a etiuq gniyas saw taht ,ega reh tA
,derewsna dna ,ylthgils deddon regnarts ehT
.mottob eht ni spordwed eht etsat ot tuo dehcterts eugnot reh ,noitilov nwo sti fO
hsiler htiw seisiad dna selppa gnitae regnarts eht
epacsdnal eht etanimulli ot daeh reh revo dna reh dniheb morf enohs nus gnisir eht fo syar tsrif eht sa
,ylteiuq dias eh ”,woN“
.dellems ron nees reven dah ehs slamina erew ereht erehw secalp gnibircsed
”.erom dna sgniht eseht lla uoy wohs llahs I dna ,em htiw emoC .ylluf ti lliW
,deunitnoc eh nehw prah nedlog a nopu sa sgnirtstraeh reh nopu deyalp rotisiv eht dna
ned reh erofeb tas ohw
,tnemnodnaba dna ssol fo esnes a yb nrot ,ti ta derats ehs sa nevE
.etsatsid htiw ssarg wodaem gnol eht otni tuo gnirats
.nepsa fo evorg a ni ezeerb eht sa teiuq sa
eh sa reh ot ecno daeh sih gniddon ,xaler ot demees regnarts ehT
,gnitnuh era uoy fI“
xof a eb ot demees ohw esroh ehT
.efil reh ni nees reve dah ehs xof god emosdnah tsom eht yb dewollof
.regnarts eht ot tnecs s'assyraN gniyrrac ,detfihs dniw ehT
.hguone ykcul erew ehs fi ynnub gnuoy a neve spahrep ro
”,ned a fo deen on evah I“
.taht ekil eugnot reh revo ekat dnim rehto eht gnivah reve llacer t'ndid tub
secalp raf eht fo srednow eht tuoba srae reh otni yltcerid gnirepsihw ,reh ot raen werd xof god eht taht assyraN ot demees tI
,woc a fo esoht ni tfelc ylniagnu prahs eht tuohtiw ssarg eht nopu
.emoc dah ehs yaw eht kcab ,elzzum reh htiw detniop ehS
,splug gniraor taerg ni ria eht ni ekat ot deralf slirtson
snommus lufyoj dna gnitepmurt a ni flesmih ot reh dellac dna
,liat sih gnihsiws ,reh dlot eh ”,tpecca ll'I“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,mih drawot selov eht fo eno deson yletilop nexiv ehT
,dehgual regnarts nedlog ehT
.yldlim reh gnieye ,dedniw ylerab doots dna
,gniteerg ni sgel dnih sih nopu deraer ohw
,tnemlaecnoc reh fo tuo yaw eht lla deppets dna ,yletilop srae reh denettalf nexiv ehT
.sthguoht reh tcelloc ot deirt dna
,emoh remrof reh drawot ecno neve kcab seye reh tsac ton did assyraN
”?raeh ot dehsiw uoy ti saw tahw“
”,uoy ot taht evael lliw I“
.woc a sa egral sa ylraen saw erutaerc ehT
.reh raeh ot dnuora eno on saw ereht hguoht ,duola ekops dna pil kcalb reh delruc neht ,flesreh ot thguoht ehs ,egnahc a rof emiT
yojne esaelP       ".orevO ovitlA"
.gnizarg sih ot denruter eh taht htiW ”.ereht eb lliw I“
,hguoht ,gnitnuh roop rof sekam moderoB