.eno ni evil reve lliw su fo enon roF
.dezingocer dnA nees llits tey
ssenippah tciped ot thguo noitcif reeuq rehtehW
,detalume eb ot toN
.decreip worros fo drows yb ,traeh ym dloheB
”noitciF reeuQ ni ytilanoitnetnI no yassE esreV knalB“ saw sihT
.neeb reven sah dna ,syawla neeb evah dluohS
.meht fo deen tey evah eW
.dlot eB ,lliw reven dna ,neeb reven sah
,htnom siht uoy rof tneserp ot dnetni ew seirots eht ot txetnoc edivorp lliw gniwollof eht taht epoh ruo si ti oS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.llew sa dlot eB sdlrow rehto tcefrep fo selat tel ,eya dnA
.eb dluohs ti sa gnol sa ton si hcaer tahT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw ro god.ecioveht
'.sdne yppah erom on' ereh yas ton od I
.denwosid dna krad
,seirots erom sa llew sa
,tey sI aibohpomoh erehw dlrow emas siht nI niamer tey I ,eya
.neeb reven sah aibohpomoh erehW sdlrow reeuq fo seoreh reeuq fo seirots roF deen eht tucrednu ot emuserp t'now I
.evas ssecnirp ssecnirp tel
:eeht llet ot epacsE enola I dnA
.tsaf stuhs rood eht erofeB tser yraew ot dial eb tsal yraew tA seow ym lla erehw dlrow gninihs eht ees oT emit ni tsuj ylno gnukcurtnegreB fO setag eht hcaer I
,dlrow thgiarts-oot eht llif dnA
,sfeirg ym rof gniveirg yB demal ecnis gnol si luos ym os tsuJ .eno evaS
.evol yleritne ton saW devol d'I evol eht lla dna
semeht eseht no seirots erom tcepxe nac uoY
,eb dluohs evol woh fo seirots em llet ,seY
.tcefrep ooT .tsuj ooT
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,floWcaM boR yb meop a evah ew yadoT
,ylpitlum dna dnuoba meht teL
,ylevitruf tub ,ecnirp evol ecnirp teL
.raw tub redneg on fo nwo sroirraw teL
.htaerb lanif ym ward I yad eht tsaltuO llahs ylekil dna ,neeb reve sah
.ydegart edisgnolA
.si evol woh fo selat osla em llet tuB
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
ssensselemoh morf
,ton sI aibohpomoh erehw sdlrow fo selat teL
.mronoreteh swal fo klub eht tsniagA raw tub redneg on fo nwo roirraw teL
,ton sI aibohpomoh erehw sdlrow gninihs riehT
.enil ytnuoc eht ta moor letom teercsiD emos ta
.thgiarts pu dnats reve ot depmarc oot stesolC ni gniworg yb
,yrotsih ym dloheB
'.sdne yppah erom on' ,ereh yas ton lliw I  floWcaM boR yb
.ticifed eht dnem ot evres ton dluow tI
,yhw ,sediseb enon dnA tsal ym ehtaerb I yad eht litnu won morF dlot erew eseht sa hcus tub selat fI .tey dnA
?sevlesruo ni ,ssalg krad a ni ,hcus dleheB ton evah su fo hcihw roF
,esiwrehto dna yppah htob
.ecioveht ta
wonk retniw dna ,noom ,tesnus fo sdog roF
tsal ym ehtaerb I yad eht litnu won morF dlot erew eseht sa hcus tub elat on fi tahT
.reh dniheb si liat esohw
.sevlesmeht ,ssalg gnilkrad a ni sa ees oT seye rieht pu snepo tsrif taht ,enoemos roF eno eht eb lliw ,lla retfa ,elat hcae roF
.reh dniheb si liat esohw ,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb daeR  .eslaf eb dluow
,noitseuq gnol a si gnireffus ro
,lliw reven dna ,neeb reven sah
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,efil a ton saW devil dah I taht efil eht taht gniveileB tsal ym ehtaerb dluow I
.seitirupmi esab fo timda evol teL
,ecneconni fo esidarap a otnI egnarts dna elbamannu shtap no del ereW ,gnos ylhtraenu yb ,srethguad dna snos ehT nwot nilemaH fo tuo nehw syad eht ni sA
.tneve s’raey siht rof tnemetats siseht a fo gnihtemos sa dednetni
eseht fo eno ylno saw hcihw tnuocca yna rof
,htnom siht yadkeew yreve gnimoc
,wonk retniw dna ,noom ,tesnus fo sdog ,roF
,”noitciF reeuQ ni ytilanoitnetnI no
.llew sa ediserif eht ta ereh su dehcuot ton sah ti mialc ton lliw I dna
.ypareht noisrevnoc leurc morf thgilf nI
.etsahcnu thgirtuo dna ydees edisgnolA .feirg edisgnolA
,ton si aibohpomoh erehw sdlrow fO era seirots ruo lla taht eb ti ton teL .niamer lliw ylekil ti ecrofrep woh dnA
,ecnirp evol ecnirp teL .eudbus ti dna
.gnimoclew oot raF
,ssecnirp evas ssecnirp teL
yassE esreV knalB“   yojne esaelP
.I sa hcus rof meht ni ecalp on evah dluoC
.tsaf sa klaw tonnac I
.htnoM edirP ot emocleW
.dlrow siht fo seirots eb oot ereht tel oS
.emit sti erofeb dlo ,ydob ym si sihT
,doolb ym si sihT
:mirg ,yhtlaehnu ,krad ,rettib edisgnolA
?eb yeht dluoc woH
.em rof thgirb oot sdlrow ni devol dna devil eB dluow seoreh ym lla fo sevol dna sevil ehT
.etanod tonnac I hcihw
'.hcaer ym nihtiw emos tup' yas rehtar I