.daeh denroh sih koohs dna hgual a tuo demoob racsO
.maertsnwod mih peews ylkciuq dluow retaw gnihsur eht dna
.wolleb s'racsO ta spley deltrats tuo tel
.kcab thgir eb ll'I ,ereh tiaW"
"?huh ,pu etad taht dessem yllaer I"
dehcaorppa ehS .yrtsimehC citemsoC ni eerged ym tog I
,ti retfa degrahc racsO
.hcneb ybraen a otni hsarc ot mih gnisuac
",thguoht I sa foorpretaw sa t'nsaw hctab taht sseug I"
.enilno teews os erew uoY" ".wonk I"
.reh ta seye sih dettab eh
",dna ,evitisnes dna ynnuf erew uoY
",pleh ruoy deen t'nod I"
",yug hguot elbirroh a ekam uoY"
.ydob sih koohs ezeens evissam A ".taht
.uoy knahT" .dehgual ehs
"!reggiD evitceteD ,yeH"
,htap eht no yadot ecrof ni tuo erew sreklaw dna ,srekib ,sretaks relloR
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.edis thgir sih revo lla gnirettalps
,yltsom ,saw llits tI
.uoy ekil yllaer I"
htap s'racsO ni yltcerid elcycib a no tibbar A
,delkcuhc eH .deknilb maS
.reh dehcaorppa TME namuh eht dna oehT
,detpmorp ehs t'ndid eh nehW
;yawa miws ot detnaw yllaer ehS
.snoitseuq mih gniksa dna seye s'racsO gnirevihs eht otni thgil a gninihs saw TME taC naisreP decaf-talf ,etihw ,yffulf A
.noitcerid sih ni kool ot denrut maS .dellac oehT ",maS"
.gnur mottob eht dnuora dnah devooh a tog racsO
.seye sih ni noitangiser
.noitaudarg erofeb em
.kcab sih ta dellac ehs
,semag fo wor tsal eht revo derettulf tah ehT
"?boj ruoy tuoba evisave os yhw dnA
,revirnwod wolb ot detfihs dah ezeerb ehT .reh derongi ro
,kcab reh no tuo deppolf ehS
fo strap 2 fo dnoces eht saw sihT
.gnur tsewol eht no sevooh sih teg ot pu flesmih dellup dna
.yhw rehtegot tup yllanif ehs dna
"?yug hguot a ekil gnitca yB"
.revo gnibmilc emit etsaw ot gnivah naht rehtar ,meht neewteb ezeeuqs ot elba saw ehs taht
.reddal eht evoba tuo dekop daeh dnuor ,nworb A
?pu-ekam ruf eht yhw"
",gniciton rof sknahT"
;ereht tog eh fi hcum rettam dluow ti taht toN
,detsetorp maS ",tuB"
,ytiruces rof dellac reh dniheb enoemoS
".mraf eht no krow ym gnirud yawa dehsaw gnitteg tpek enim nehw detartsurf saw I ecnis ,puekam ruf foorpretaw ot syaw no siseht D.hP ym etorw I
.elbaresim dekool racsO
.eno elttac a ton ,gnikram esroh a sI"
,deirc maS "!on ,racsO" .pmuj gninnur rehtona ekam ot deraperp eh sa
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,deredduhs dna eson reh delknirw ehS
gninaelc hguoroht a deen ot gniog saw klawedis ehT
.elgnairt etihw eht hcuot ot eson sih pu regnif devooh a nar eh ",sihT
.detrons dna decamirg eH ".dnal
.elbaeciton erom neve sehctap etihw eht gnikam
.dereetnulov d'eh ebyam ro
,deddon dna dehgis racsO ".kcab
.pu ti gnirevoc detrats I litnu ylsseltneler ti tuoba desaet teg ot desu I
.dekcinap I ,nosrep ni teem ot detnaw uoy dias uoy nehw ,yawynA .em esucxE"
,teknalb lamreht eht rednu gnirevihs saw eH
.stnecs revir eht fo tser eht derewoprevo ti taht hguone dab saw hcnets eht tub
.teerts ybraen eht no dekrap ecnalubma eht ot ssarg eht ssorca ffo degdurt sTME eerht eht rehtegot dna yawa denrut eH ".teknalb
.reh ot gnirutseg saw dna eson sih morf wap a detfil d'eH
,nwod deretsalp saw ruf sih dna
.oot ,uoy tnioppasid ot tnaw t'ndid I
.gniliar eht deraelc eh sa tsuj tah eht fo mir eht revo desolc dnah devooh siH
.dnal no naht retaw eht ni retsaf hcum saw ehS
.drah gnitnap ,ereht gnuh dna gnur eht revo pu woble eno tog eH
,htreb ediw a meht evag enoyreve taht tnaem llems s'racsO tub
.gnihtyna naht desuma erom dekool eh tub
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.wodahs ni neddih ecaf sih flah tuohtiw retteb dekool eH
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
,sdrawA yraretiL OEL owt dna drawA ltoyoC a now sah ohw ohw
eye eno dnuora etihw fo hctap depahssim a rof tpecxe
ecnef knil-niahc hgih toof thgie eht gniraelc
.seye nworb gib sih htiw reh ta gnicnalg yllanoisacco ,dnuorg eht ot gniklat llits saw eh ",haeY"
.miws dluoc ehs sa tsaf sa retaw eht hguorht tohs dna
.racsO sdrawot revo delddaw dna teef reh ot flesreh dehsup ehS
"?ynapmoc scitemsoc ruf lacol ehT"
.tuo dnif ot tiaw ot emit on saw ereht tub
.puekam tuoba msaisuhtne suoivbo sih ta delims maS ".gnizama s'tahT"
",pu-ekam rof evol ym derevocsid I woh saw eyd ruf gniyuB"
.tah warts reh saw
.spih reh no swap reh gnittup ,denethgiarts maS ".dat a tsuJ"
.mih dettops ehs litnu
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.kcab daeh reh denarc maS
.yarps knuks neerg htiw derettalps gnihtolc ,fles delggardeb dna neddos sih ta nwod dekool dna decamirg racsO
,warts trohs eht nward evah tsum tac eht desseug ehS
.oom a naht krab a ekil erom dnuos gnilbmur a tuo gnittel
.teknalb eht peek nac uoY .em yb eniF"
.detnuoc taht thguoht eht saw ti tub
.tsal ta reh ot gnidnopser
.mih dnuora rethgit teknalb eht gnillup ,sredluohs sih dehcnuh eh
.retaw evoba daeh sih peek ot sgel dna smra sih gnilddap
.tsael ta ,cimrehtopyh t'nsi eh tub ,dellihC"
.racsO tih dah yarps eht lla toN
.airtuN a yb detrats saw ynapmoc taht"
.racsO ot denrut ehS ".pu
.weiv fo dleif reh fo tuo detemmulp eh sa
.flesruoy ti edam uoy ekil dnuos ti sekam 'dednetni uoy sA'"
ecaf sih dessorc esirprus lacimoc fo noisserpxe nA
racsO ot skcab rieht htiw rellorts a gnihsup elpuoc knuks A
.yad remmus dnaltroP tcefrep eht fo egatnavda gnikat
.rewol detfird dna
.racsO ta nwod dekool maS
.tih yeht sa decamirg ehS
.htap gniklaw dna revir eht morf lavitsef eht detarapes taht
”seulB etaD dnilB“
.wap a pu dleh ehs ",tuB"
.ylper rieht raeh ot gnitiaw tuohtiw retaw eht otni evod dna denrut ehS
.gnihcter dna gniggag kcab llef liart eht no slamina eht fo tser eht tub
edis eht ot derettulf tah ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.teknalb lamreht ynihs a ni pu depparw ,klawedis eht no gnittis saw racsO
.snroh sih morf knil-niahc fo sparcs gnikahs racsO ees ot emit ni semag lavinrac eht fo owt neewteb morf degreme maS
.htap a flesmih raelc ot ylduol gnioom
.mih sdrawot gnimmiws ydaerla ,dias maS ",ti ekam ot gniog t'nera uoy esiwrehto ,uoy hsup pleh ll'I ,ereH"
.meht ees dluoc ehs denigami tsomla ehs gnorts os ,mih ffo dellor knits fo sevaW
,maertsnwod raf oot eb d'eh
.mih retfa pu detrats maS pu teef wef a saw eh nehW
detsuahxe dekool racsO tub ,esolc siht gnimlehwrevo tsomla saw rodo knuks eht
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.won desufnoc ylhguoroht saw ehS "?hctaB"
maercs dehctip hgih a tuo tel
.racsO morf kcab llew doots
reddal eht fo pot eht revo pu flesreh dellup ehs emit eht yB
.deggurhs tac ehT
.llems fo esnes roop a dah semitemos slamina delzzum talf esoht draeh d'ehS
.tah ruoY" .depsag eh
.retaw eht fo tuo dnah rehto sih detfil dna dewollaws racsO
liat reh no kcab dexaler maS
reh raeh t'ndid rehtie racsO tub ,delley maS
.knits tnegnup eht morf gniretaw erew seye reh ydaerla tub ,elpuoc knuks eht dehcaer ehs erofeb detlah d'ehS
.tnedive emaceb noitsuahxe s'racsO ,pu yawflaH
,ti rof gnihton saw erehT
,reh fo revirnwod syaw a ni nellaf dah racsO
.resolc teg ot gnilliwnu
.hcet bal a saw I dias I nehw eil t'ndid ,hu ,I
.niaga htap siht esu ot gnilliw eb dluow elpoep erofeb
.racsO htiw pu hctac ot gniog reven saw ehs ecnis
.flesmih ot yltsom ,derettum eh
.thgirb os saw ti noom eht morf nees neeb evah dluoc elims s'racsO ".revo-
,tuo deyarps oog wolley hsineerg dna yb degrahc eh sa racsO ta liat reh detfil rehtom knuks ehT
.yllufthguoht nihc sih debbur tac ehT
"?kcab ti gnirb dna tuo siht llif woc eht evah uoy lliW"
,kcab gnuh TME namuh eht dna oehT
.taht lla morf yawa teg ot ,trats hserf a teg ot dnaltroP ot emac I
sregnif sih ni dehctulC
.lufetarg saw ehs
.emoh tog ehs nehw htab eciuj otamot gnol ecin a evah ot gniog saw ehS
nees d'ehs swoc tsom naht rekciht dna regnol erew sehsal siH
.ssarg eht otni sleeh revo daeh dehctip eH
.flesreh desruc ehs dna
.tnorfretaw kcolbrednic eht fo yarg eht tsniaga tuo doots senil yarg rekrad fo seires A
.yltnasaelp tsehc s'maS ni detarbiv taht elbmur wol a
.reh ta kcab ti dehsup dna wap a pu dleh maS tub
,revir eht otni gnillaf morf snairtsedep tpek egde eno gnola gniliar A
.knuks fo knuts racsO morf reh no nwod gnippird retaw ehT
,teknalb lamreht a tuo koohs namuh ehT
.racsO dna maS htob sserdda ot pu denethgiarts tac ehT ".tsael
.egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy
.revir eht sdrawot dna semag yawdim eht revo tah reh deirrac ezeerb ehT
;ssergorp fo etar tnerruc sih ta reddal eht ot ti ekam ot gniog t'nsaw eH
.tnereffid demees gnihtemos ,tuB
.klawedis eht otno debmilc maS sa feiler fo kaeuqs a tuo tel oehT
.poc a erew uoy taht dna swoc eht derebmemer I
,edis eht ot elcycib sih dekrej dna
,klat siht evah ot ecalp eht ro emit eht yllaer t'nsaw sihT
.sgel dna smra sih ni romert eht ees dluoc ehs woleb morf nevE
".scitauqA rof stcudorp ni gnizilaicepS"
,mussopO na dna namuH a
.pu bmilc eht rof revocer dna tser ot ecnahc a racsO evig dluow ti tub
",nwod rehtruf og ot evah ew ,ereh tuo teg t'nac eW"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ecilop eht rof esle enoemos dna
.deksa maS "?pu uoy tsoob pleh ot em deen uoy oD"
.ezeerb eht ni yltneg gnitallicso
.reh dniheb pu gnimoc reciffo enipucrop eht dna
.yarps eht tsniaga gnitniuqs ,ezag sih dewollof maS ".reddaL"
.swap htob htiw eson sih gnirevoc ,reh dlot eh ",keer uoY"
.ti hguorht thgir degrahc d'eh erehw ecnef eht ni nrot eloh a saw erehT
.reh rof hguone dooG
".dednetni I sa dekrow ,tsael ta ,taht no gnifoorp-retaw eht ,haeY"
,relleK nosidaM naI yb ”seulB etaD dnilB“
,tnorfretaw eht no demuser dah ciffart nairtsedeP
,poc slian-sa-hguot a er'uoY
eson reh dewollof ehS
llems fo esnes a gnikcal mih tuoba sseug reh taht reh dlot noisserpxe eneres s'TME tac eht ta ecnalg A
gninnur deppots maS
.daeh reh no gniht yggos eht dehcrep dna ti koot ehS ".uoy
,yarps knuks fo rodo gnitaesuan eht rof lufetarg eb d'ehs thguoht reven ehS
.egdirB enrohtwaH eht tsaP"
",emaG namgnortS eht dna yrellaG gnitoohS eht ta reilrae scitna ruoy naht erom raf em gnisserpmi er'uoy won thgir ,yltsenoH ?I dluow yhW"
.mih pleh ot evah d'ehs
.tniop reh ekam ot klawedis eht no yllufecrof liat reh deppals maS
ereh trapa hguone raf erew srab ehT
.pu yaw ruo no er'ew ,ereht pu yatS"
.meht sdrawot gnigrahc llub degarne eht was elpoep sa denediw seye dna denrut sdaeH
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.mih ta kcab elims tub pleh t'ndluoc maS ".flesruoy
.tah warts tnarticlacer reh retfa desahc llits racsO ecnatsid eht nI
,detnurg racsO ",oN"
.sseccus hcum tuohtiw erohs eht sdrawot tnerruc eht tsniaga thguof eH
hcaorppa s'maS tA
”seulB etaD dnilB“:yojne esaelP
?kcab sih tsniaga gnihsup ,elgna na ta mih ot pu maws ehs fi ebyaM
,demmid elims siH ".noitidnoc
.niaga gnikaeps nigeb ot mih rof tnemom a detiaw maS .tnelis llef eH ".oot
.citsaisuhtne dna ,trams ,evitisnes saw ohw
.skcolbrednic eht otni fooh a dekcik eh ",m'I dna
- og ot stnaw eh fi mih ekat nac eW"
.tcaf taht no gnitnemmoc no eugnot reh dloh reh edam rehtruf detalfed eh yaw eht tub ,erofeb sesroh no kram taht nees reve ylno d'ehS
.kcab sih tih swap s'maS nehw tcejbo t'ndid tub ,delbmurg eh
,ecnahc sih was racsO
".on ,yrassecen yltcirts t'nsi ti tub - ereht retsaf tol a pu mih mraw dluoc ew
.hteet gnirettahc hguorht dias racsO ",latipsoh oN"
,racsO sa delggardeb sa dekool ehs erus saw ehS
.sgel trohs reh gnisruc
"?latipsoh eht ot og ot deen eh seoD"
.won deye ediw reh ta gnirats saw eH "?dnim t'nod uoY"
reddal eht depsarg eh troffe fo tnurg a htiW ".tsisni uoy fI"
.meht dnuora elcric ediw a ni ecaps raelc a gnivael
.koob tekcit wolley a pu dleh reciffo enipucroP ehT
.reh dnuora dray a ylno ot nwod saw ytilibisiv dna ykrum saw revir ehT
.revir eht otni llef reilrae htiw saw I nrohgnol ehT"
...llems eht ,em pleh sseddog ,tub ,flesym ti tneserp dna revo og ot deirt I"
,etalfed ot demees racsO ".drah
.tahw tniopnip ot deirt ehs sa mih ta detniuqs ehS
?em sserpmi dluow tca taht kniht d'uoy d'yhw ,oS
.spmuj evisserpmi sih etipsed
.tnaem ehs egdirb hcihw wonk t'ndluow eh esruoc fO
"!tah a tsuj s'tI !pots ,racsO"
.evoba morf emac slley ehT
"?oot ,aracsam no evah uoY"
,mih retfa delddaw maS   2 fo 2 traP
"!slavinrac oN" "?taht s'tahW"
.nam fo erom eb ot em gnillet tpek lla swoc eht emoh kcaB ?yllufhturT"
,enilno htiw gnittahc neeb d'ehs llub eht saw ereH .dias maS
.daeherof sih fo elddim eht ni elgnairt etihw a dna
.dnal no lufecarg ro tsaf ton erew srevaeB
sgel sih gnipmup dna daeh sih gnirewol
.gnissarrabme s'tI" "?tser eht dna"
",ruoy deveirter I"
,nwod wols ro eciton ot mees neve t'ndid racsO
,ti pleh t'ndluoc maS ".tah
noitcerid reh nrut neve t'ndid racsO ".egdirB
".uoy sserpmi ot detnaw I"
,sdaeh rieht potrevo detaolf tah ehT
,od I ,ti etaicerppa I"
.sredluohs sih gnihcnuh dna gnur eht revo nwod gnipmuls
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.drah oot gniyrt er'uoy tub ,racsO yug teews a ekil mees uoy dna
.ruenerpertne tuokaerb wen tsettoh s'dnaltroP fo dlihcniarb eht erew yehT .dias maS
dehcnub s'gel s'racsO
.hctab tset a s'tI .did I" .yawa decnalg eH
.evoba pu erehwemos morf emac sneris detuM
.eciov s'rettO eht dezingocer ehs tub ,serutaef tuo ekam t'ndluoc ehS
.noitnetta sih teg ot ecaf s'racsO ta retaw gnihsalps ,delley ehs "?maertsnwod egdirb eht eeS"
".ni llef eh nehw retaw eht fo yna ni dehtaerb eh fi ainomuenp gnihctac fo regnad ni llits s'eH"
,llew rehtar gnimmiws yllautca saw racsO
.taht hsilpmocca ot yaw tseb eht tuoba kniht ot dnoces a deraps ehS
oehT dettops ehs eye reh fo renroc eht fo tuO
.neppah dluow tahw etapicitna ot elba
dna noitciF degnaF yb stneicnA eht fo lautiR
.denethgirb racsO ".airtuN
.tac eht gnisserdda ,deksa maS "?eh si woH"
.enipucroP eht dna oehT ot revo delddaw ehS
.klawedis eht evoba htuos tah eht gniwolb
.uoy tuoba dekil I tahw saw tahT
.meht ta delley maS ",pleh rof llaC
.delf dah snairtsedep eht fo tsom won yB
.dnal yrd no pu kcab era ew ecno noissucsid siht hsinif dluohs ew spahreP"
.kcab gnipmuj dna elzzum sih gnilknirw erofeb ,guh kciuq a reh evag eH
.reciffo enipucroP eht ot koob eht denruter ehs enod saw eh nehW
.pu dellac maS ",ti od nac uoY"
,dworc gniworg eht hguorht depollag racsO
,ton ro miws dluoc eh fi wonk t'ndid ehS
.tsal ta dias ehs
.bmilc eht fo redniamer eht rof mih ot tnemegaruocne delley ehS
.tniop emos ta tah yobwoc sih tsol d'eh taht deciton won ylno ehS .deddon racsO
.koob derefforp eht koot dna dehgis maS "...llems
.retaw eht fo tuo yaw on htiw llaw reehs a llits saw ereht tniop siht ta
,enipucroP eht dlot ehs ",woc a ton ,llub a s'eh os ,yug a s'eH"
.racsO ot denruter maS dna ,tfel yeht sa evaw elttil a reh gnireffo oehT
.kcab delley ehS "!oehT"
"?erofeb nat lla ruf ruoy t'nsaW" .desuap ehs
.reh dnuora smra sih gnulf oehT sa detpurretni saw ehS .dias maS
.ria eht otni hgih ,pu dednuob eh dna
.reddal eht ot ti ekam ot deganam yeht rehtegoT
,oot ,krow ffo worromot evah ot neppah I"
.rehtegot rettalc slliuq reh lla gnikam
.gnitaluclac ,racsO dna reddal eht neewteb dekool ehS
,ecaf sih ot derutseg ehs ",sulP
.mih ot revo maws dna decafrus maS
.noitidnoc eno si erehT"
.salumrof tcudorp eht ngised I dna ,ekil eht dna gnitekram eht ,sgniht eht fo edis ssenisub eht snur ehs ,haeY"
revo koob eht deirrac maS
.hgual ecin a dah eH
.llub eht dedrager ehs sa smra reh dessorc dna
.syug rehto eht ekil t'nerew uoy esuaceb enilno uoy dekil I" .dehgis maS
.seson rieht revo swap ro sdnah rieht dleh llA
,sTME erom owt dna ,reciffo enipucroP eht htiw gnola ,oehT
si koob tsewen sih dna
.edis sih ta retaw dedaert maS
htgnel s'regnif a ria eht ni tuoba gnicnad saw tah eht dna retsaf saw ezeerb eht tub ,tsaf saw eH
",mraw em tpek ruf yM .ti deen t'nod I"
.tcerroc neeb ylbaborp dah
revirnwod flesreh detniop ehS
.woleb teef ytrof
.msiladnav dna roivaheb sselkcer rof tekcit a htiw tuo dellif saw mrof pot ehT .deggurhs ohw
.tnerruc eht tsniaga yawdaeh yna ekam ot remmiws hguone gnorts a t'nsaw eh dna
hcihw rof ,maS morf yawa tnecs eht deirrac ezeerb ehT
,ffo koot enipucroP eht dna oehT ,enod boJ
.ereh mih evael erad t'ndid ehs dna
.revo-od-etad tsrif a rof noonretfa worromot pu em kcip ot uoy tcepxe I os
.gniliar eht rof detrad dna desruc maS
,hcaer s'racsO fo tuo
.ylyrd dednopser ehs
.ruf reh no nus mraw eht gniyojne
.mrof eht otni noitamrofni sih deretne racsO elihw detiaw dna
".lufituaeB gnimmiwS trats depleh I
".hcaeb a ot teg ot ti rednu miws ot deen eW"