sserd sseleveels ehT
,oehT saw riap eht fo enO
.teef flah a dna owt nwo s'maS naht rellat ylerab doots racsO
"?ereh pu uoy thguorb taht boj eht t'nsi naicinhceT baL oS"
;sblub eht detnuoc maS .eerhT .owT .enO
,racsO dna reh ot dias ycatS
.gnilkceh nageb dna
.slamina reggib neve egnellahc ot detarbilac era sgniht esoht wonk uoY
.ydal'm ,esruoc fO" "?ni og ew llahS"
.deretsulf ,ni tuc maS ".desirprus eb d'uoY" ".dlohpu
,dleh ehs walc raeb fo eceip eht no nwod kaeb sti deppans dna denrut drib eht oS
.eerht fo tuo owt tseB"
.uoy gnitnemilpmoc saw I !ton m’I"
.gninrom remmus siht ytterp ylralucitrap saw tnorfretaw ehT
.eltneg ylgnisirprus saw pirg sih hguohtla
.sdik s'rekraP ot evig ot nooccar hsulp elprup dna egnaro hsirag a detceles maS ".sezirp
.mih morf ti ekat ot mra na rednu hsulp eht dekcut ohw
.semit lareves deppop elfir ria ehT
.tegrat a dnuof tohs hcaE .pop-pop-
.sgniw sti htiw ecaf dna daeh eht tuoba reh gnitaeb saw llugaes laref a retal dnoces a dna
.epoh I ,sgniht dab llA"
sdnuorg lavitseF ehT
.sserd eht yb delpmur neeb dah taht ruf eht gniltteser nageb dna
,pu depmuj kcup elttil ehT
"!trohs os s'eh ,tuB !llub a s'eH"
.snroh sih fo eno no thguac tellam eht fo egde rebbur eht dna ,daeh sih denrut ylthgils eh gnuws eh sA
,trihs nretsew derediorbme ,etihw a dna snaej erow eH
.etalp rekirts s'namgnortS eht raen pu denil sezis suoirav fo stellam rebbur fo enil a ot detniop dna edisa deppets peehs ehT
.strac doof eht ta gnirats dnuora deleviws saw daeh reh tub
gniliec eht morf gnuh sezirp ekhctohct ylemoH
"?thgir ,eerht fo tuo owt tseB"
noitnetta s'racsO teg ot devaw maS
.pu til seye kcalb s'rekraP ".uoy
,recnad a ekil deklaw ycatS
.setunim net ni pu uoy kcip ll'ew ,yawynA"
.mih ta kcab debbol maS
.gurhs eht raeh yllacitcarp dluoc maS
.tol a taht teg I"
.detrons eh dna noisserpxe deifirroh a ni delknirw elzzum s'racsO
koob tsewen sih dna
.namow nooccar elbmin eht ot txen gniklaw elihw yllaicepse
.tsud fo ffup elttil a pu gnidnes
.racsO ta regnif a detniop dna maS dna racsO dettops eH
dnab cirbaf a htiw tah nus warts etuc a dah ehS
.srehto eht htiw kcab ti gnicalp dna tellam eht pu gnikcip yllausac ,dias peehs eht ",emit txen kcul retteB"
,sbew reh no hguor erew spit regnif ekil-fooh s'racsO
.etacilpud ot epoh reven dluoc maS taht yaw a ni gnola gnipoh dna gnippiks
.erutcip eliforp enilno sih ekil yltcaxe dekool eh
.elims a htiw reh ot txen pu deppets ohw ycatS ot derutseg maS ekahs eht morf kcab werd racsO nehW
"!niw ot skcuD toohS"
.maS naht rellat tib a llits saw eh tub
kraP tnorfretaW ta devirra yehT
.retnec daed etalp eht tih wolb sih emit sihT
.walc raeb eht ffo seceip owt erot racsO
.sdne llub eht racsO htiw etad s’maS woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,maS ot eno dereffo eH
",stohs net teg uoY"
eldnah a htiw tellam a detceles racsO
devaeh tsehc sih dna deworran seye s'racsO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,skcud nedoow eht ta lerrab eht nwod dethgis
.nrohediW racsO ,etad yM"
nemlortap DPP ytud no fo riap a ot devaw maS sdnuorg lavitsef eht edisnI
enipucrop a ,rentrap siH
,rorrim eht fo tnorf ni delriwt dna pu ti dleh ehS
.woc a ton ,rekraP ,llub a s'eH" ".woc ruoy s'tI"
.reviR ettemalliW eht gnola
,pu dna redluohs sih ffo ti detfil eH
.sehsaleye kciht ,gnol yrev erew yehT
",txen emaG namgnortS tuB
naorg a desserppus maS
.skcud gnicnuob elttil eht sdrawot demia eh sa yldrawkwa ti dleh dna
.meht tuohtiw lavinrac eht ot gniog er'uoy taht suoiruf eb tsum yehT"
",doof tsuj ,semag ni detseretni ton m'I tub ,sknahT"
.ynapmoc tahw ro saw noitisop taht yltcaxe tahw tuoba eugav elttil a neeb dah tub
,sdrawA yraretiL OEL owt dna drawA ltoyoC a now sah ohw ohw
",rehtegot sedir eht no og nac ew nehT ?ruoh na flah ni pu teem ew tuoba woH"
.erab kcab reppu dna smra reh tfel taht sredluohs reh revo sparts dessorcssirc htiw ,hgiht-dim tuoba reh tih
?ti t'nsi ,deroloc ylthgirb ytterp si tI" .dehgual ehS
tol gnikrap s'eebyB ekaL eht otni denrut nav-inim s'rekraP
.depoord liat dna srae htiw ,dessarrabme kool ot ecarg eht gnivah ,dias eh ",yrros ,hA"
.tnorf ni selop eht fo hcae nwod dna
skeew owt tsal eht rof enilno htiw dettahc d'ehs taht saw yug lufthguoht
",uoy teem ot desaelP"
.edis hcae denil latot neetfif
.niw uoY .enif s'ti ,oN"
.ti ekil thgim sdik ruoy thguoht I tuB
.deppots dna ssertsid reh deciton racsO tsael tA
.ycatS dna rekraP teem og ot emiT"
elfir eht pu dekcip eH ".nrut ruoY"
.sdnah devooh htoob htiw tellam eht gnippirg ,pu denil eH
.sserd eht no llup dluoc ehs os deb eht no ti dial dna enohp-rekaeps ot revo enohp reh dekcilc ehS .delworg maS
tnorfretaw eht fo edis tsew eht fo yteritne eht pu koot
.doohrobhgien eebyB ekaL reh ni pu nworg d'ohw retto nael a
.edis rehto s'racsO no deklaw yeht taht os drawrof rekraP gniggard ,dias ycatS ",racsO oS"
".lleb eht morf yawa owt ylnO"
",ytriht ni ereh kcab teeM .eruS"
,dias racsO ",tsrif seidaL"
"?namgnortS eht em wohs uoy tuoba woH"
.wap reh mih dereffo dna racsO ot revo tnew maS elihw kcab gnuh ycatS ".ma I"
.kcab tah sih detlit dna
,ti rof debbarg dna deirc maS ",tah yM"
.nooccar eht ot yletilop dias racsO
.dias rekraP ",lleW"
,nageb maS "—ot deen on s'ereht ,yllaer ,racsO"
.strac doof eht sdrawot detniop ehs yaw reh decnalg eh nehW
"?walc raeb emos tnaW"
.racsO ot derutseg dna ,flesreh ot gniht ylgu eht gnigguh
tsehc sih pu deffup oehT
.net fo tuo net tih uoY"
"!yob a ton dna nam a er'uoy ydal ruoy wohS !htgnerts ruoy tset ,pu thgir petS"
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.gnignis nageb sbuc sih dnuorgkcab eht nI ".taht
.ria eht otni dna yaw pu ti detfil dna
.reggiD ,nooccar eciN"
.revo nellaf evah dluow ehs ro ,liat talf reh htiw flesreh deidaets ehS
# .kcod eht ffo deppets maS sa
".refsnart t'ndid strec ocixeM weN ym fo emos tub ,yrtsimehc ni D.hP a htiw raey tsal detaudarg I"
,snaej sih fo stekcop eht otni dekcut smra delcsum
",gnidnatsrednusim thgils a tsuJ"
.dlohpu ot noitatuper a evah I ,lla retfA
fo strap 2 fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.gninrom eht rof denepo lavitseF esoR dnaltroP eht rof setag eht sa
.woble sih koot dna tuo dehcaer ehs etilop eb ot ,revewoH
.mutnemom reh pots ot liat talf ,ediw reh gnisu
",etad eht gnirud taht od ton retteb yehT"
,emaG namgnortS eht gninnam eeyolpme ehT ".thgirlA"
.etalp rekirts eht fo tnorf ni revo deppets eh sa dereggats racsO
derevocer tub esirprus htiw detaelb peehs ehT
.snaej dna ,trihs nretseW
"?txen yrt ot tnaw uoy od emag tahw oS
.deretsulf tib a m'I yrros m'I"
.thgirpu erew stegrat eht fo lla dna stohs fo tuo saw racsO nehw dias ehs ",em rof dekrow tI .ddo s'tahT"
.yrellaG gnitoohS eht ot detniop neht dna semag deyarra eht redisnoc ot deppots maS
.meht fo lla rof stekcit hguone yub ot dereffo ylsuoicarg racsO erehw
.wolley thgirb a detniap saw dna "ereH dloS stekciT" daer taht pot eht revo ngis a dah tI
"?aedi doog a siht kniht ew od ,oS"   2 fo 1 traP
.retnuoc eht dniheb esoognom eht ot stekcit rieht evag hcae dna htoob yrellaG gnitoohS eht ot revo yaw rieht edam yeht os ,deerga maS ".eerht
.enod saw ehs nehw demialcxe esoognom eht "!woW"
tub evitcartta eb thgim eh ;tsaf llihnwod gniog saw etad sihT .flesreh desitsahc dna meht gnirimda flesreh thguac ehS
.ecalp ni tah eht nip reh pleh dluoc ycatS efiw s'rekraP
daer kcab eht ta rennab ehT
,denoitroporpsid dna drawkwa tlef ehs dnal no tub ,suoretxed dna lufecarg tlef syawla ehs retaw nI
.racsO ta gnilims ,dias maS
.seitud reh ot kcab noitnetta reh gninrut erofeb roivaheb s'oehT ta daeh reh koohs dna
"?meht noitseuq uoy erofeb ti htiw stcepsus eht dnilb ot gninnalp uoY"
",etad dnilb no gniog era uoy eveileb t'nac llits I" .tcefreP
".ahtnamaS eb tsum uoY"
.seye reh dellor maS ".woc
.gnikrap etacol ot ffo gnivird erofeb etag eht yb maS dna ycatS deppord rekraP
.pot eht ta gnog eht gnir ot gniog saw ti erus saw maS dna ,pu welf kcup elttil ehT
.reh ta sehsaleye sih dettab dna detuop racsO
.pu dekrep eciov sih neht tub
.edirts ni gnipins s'ycatS koot racsO tiderc sih oT
.toohs ot woh wonk d'uoy taht mraf elttac a no pu gniworg uoy htiw thguoht I tub
"!uoy rof ti teg ll'I"
.gnihtemos gnissim saw ti tub ,doog dekool tI
.nekops dah racsO sa denediw dah seye reH .deksa maS
,maS rof mra sih dexelf eh
,kcab deppets ehs enod saw ehs nehW
.mih ta kcab dennirg maS ".reggiD
dehcaorppa ycatS dna maS sa hcuols sih morf denethgiarts racsO
,egatnavda riafnu na fo tib a evah od I sseug I" .delims ehS ".teb
.ffo erew ycatS dna rekraP detsetorp dluoc maS erofeB .dias racsO
,sserd eht dehctam taht wob dna
,maS ta dekniw dna dennirg racsO ".tirips
yllufeur delims ,tnemtraped eht fo naretev emit gnol a dna
!llub tekcop ,ereht uoY"
.troffe htiw gnikahs smra sih
”seulB etaD dnilB“
,reh ta revo decnalg dna
,oot ti dellems maS
.draug ffo reh thguac taht enilno nekops-tfos dna teews os neeb d'eH
.pu mih reehc ot gniyrt ,dias maS
.etad tsrif a rof gnilaever oot saw ti tub
.yawa denrut dna nwod tah yobwoc sih dellup racsO
.enot derutan doog a ni denraw maS
.drib eht ta taws ot nooccar hsulp eht deppord dna demaercs maS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.yawdim eht detixe yeht nehw meht rof gnitiaw erew ycatS dna rekraP
”seulB etaD dnilB“
.deddon tub ,tib a detalfed eH
.draobkcab eht no tuoba gnivaew dna gnibbob nageb skcud elttil eht dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.kool ytrid a maS tohs ycatS
sredluohs daorb sih deggurhs racsO ".toohs
.swap reh otni selfir ria eht fo eno gnisserp
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
"?tsetnoc gnitoohs a ni uoy gnitaeb em fo diarfa t'nsi uoy ekil yobwoc gnorts a yleruS"
.kcab deppilf skcud eht fo enon tub
snroh gnol owt eht edih ot gnihton did tah yobwoc siH
.rewsna eht tuoba suoiruc osla
,drow sih ot eurT
.yks eulb eht tsniaga skceps etihw
.semag eht yalp nac ew erofeb stekcit yub ot deen ew tuB"
.efiw s'rekraP ,ycatS m'I
.nwod kcab detemmulp ti
.tellam eht kcab koot peehs nrohgib eht sa
.dnuorg eht no liat reh deppals maS .delworg racsO
.eybdoog gniyas tuohtiw pu gnuh rekraP ".setunim
.daeh sih naht reggib hguod deirf fo eceip a deniatnoc taht etalp repap a deirrac rekraP
,gnignis sbuc reh draeh evah ton tsum ehS ".t'ndid
.edisa gnippets ,dias esoognom eht
.eihsulp s'maS dettops eh nehT
"!ffo ti llup nac eh fi ees s'teL
.esolc taht teg ot hguone drah ti tih uoy desserpmi m'I ,em tsurT
.ecnef eht tsniaga tser ot kcab tneb rehto eht dna ,dednetxe gel eno
.dias maS ",enif s'tI"
.etad elbuod eht fo esoprup eht detaefed ti
,ynnuf eht erehw derednow ehS
.ybraen strac doof fo enil eht morf revo detfaw ragus deirf dna taf fo amora eht
.tirips ton ,ezis ni ynit ylno er'uoy taht ereht lrig ruoy wohs ot ecnahc ruoy si sihT
"?emag txen eht skcip renniw yrellaG gnitoohS eht tuoba woH" .dias racsO
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
dna noitciF degnaF yb stneicnA eht fo lautiR si
hsurb a pu dekcip ehs sa dehgual maS ".rettis
"!wonk I ,ho ,ro ,llabeekS yalp rehtar uoy t'ndluoW"
,eert a ni gnittis ,woc a dna revaeb A"
.ycatS ot txen dnats ot meht dniheb morf pu gnimoc ,deksa rekraP "?ynnuf os s'tahW"
.ekoj a neeb dah ti thguoht ehs ebyam ro
.etulas prahs a reh evag dna
.tekcit rehtona peehs eht dednah eH ".niagA"
.ecnartne s'yawdim eht ot kcab dedaeh yeht sa gnihtyna yas t'ndid racsO ".ycatS
,neve ynit ,llub a rof trohs saw eh
.rennam gnidnecsednoc ylrevo dna gnidrow detauqitna eht ta
.raew ot ton etuc oot saw ti ,llitS
dewac llug a daehrevO
.revo meht devaw eh sa
.taeh eht ffo egde eht gnikat ria dloc eht
.tops gniteem eht ot kcab yaw eht fo tser eht tnelis saw racsO ".esolc
poP .reggirt eht dellup dna
,esop tnedifnoc tey lausac a ni
,ffo delddaw maS
".emaG namgnortS eht no uoy sserpmi nac I"
;gnol taht racsO htiw enola tfel gnieb tuoba erus t'nsaw ehS .detatiseh maS
.ti ta doog hcum reveN" .yraw seye
.ti retfa gnigrahc ,deirc racsO
.yobwoc demaercs tiftuo eritne eht rehtegot dna
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
,tah yobwoc sih ot derutseg ehS ".nom'c ,hO"
".gniog erew ew erehw meht llet t'ndid ,hu ,eW" .desuap rekraP ".meht
.delwocs ycatS tub dehgual maS ".tol
"!tih dnoces taht htiw boj dooG"
;drawkwa tib a saw tI
.foor eht ni hctah eht aiv detixe dna moor gnivil reh fo renroc eht ni tes reddal eht debmilc ehs
,etag eht ta ecnO
.teef debbew elttil ybbuts reh no tsaf yrev t'nsaw hcihw
.tops ot ysae saw etad s'maS
.rekirts eht fo egde eht gnittih ylerab ,ediw tnew wolb siH
.maS ot woble sih tuo dleh racsO ".ydal'm
,yawa degniw ti sa tah reh tih teef s'llug ehT
,ycnangerp tsal reh morf deirrac llits ehs sdnuop artxe eht etipseD
.t'ndid ehs ,llew ,tub ,uoy tuoba hcum os su dlot maS yas ot ekil d'I
,pu til ecaf s'racsO
.elims elttil a maS evag eh dna
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
"?gnivil a rof od uoy od tahW"
.denediw seye s'ycatS ".nrohediW
.tekcit a peehs eht evag dna
",kcab teg uoy nehw ruf ruoy no ti llems ot gniog er'yehT"
.redluohs sih revo ti detfeh eh sa troffe htiw gnitnurg
".revaeb a eb d'uoy thguoht I timda I
"!taht ekil uoy fo egatnavda gnikat ,dab leef I woN"
,dias eh eciov napdaed a nI
.sdrow reh revo gnillum saw eh depoh ehs dna
.semag lavinrac fo swor eht sdrawot gninrut ,noitcerid detfihs eh yltpurbA ".tsom
,seye dna ruf nworb yksud reh detnemilpmoc der ehT
.tsom ta skeew erom wef a rof eb ot gniog ylno s'ti tub ,oN"
redluohs reh htiw pu enohp eht gnipporp ,dias maS
nirg ediw a meht dehsalf eH
.pu thgil ot nageb sedis eht no sblub eht dna
”seulB etaD dnilB“
"?eye ruoy hctac gnihtynA"
.hceercs a htiw yawa gnihcnual erofeb wap reh fo eerf ti gnippir
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy
.yrellaG gnitoohS ,eniF" .enog dah
.tuo yaw eht no moorhtab reh morf snip ybbob fo lufwap a debbarg ehS
.sdrib ekil depahs stegrat dna selfir ria dah eno ralucitrap sihT
aera tegrat eht fo edis eht no nottub a tih eh hceeps sih dehsinif eh nehW ".ezirp
tah ediw eht thguac ezeerb ehT
.nrettap yelsiap der a htiw sserd nus nottoc a saw eno sihT
.erom ecno rorrim eht ni flesreh dedrager dna denrut maS
.daeh sih morf tuo devruc taht
.ffo tuc gnignis eht dna gnimmals rood a fo dnuos eht saw erehT "--.s .s .i .k
.enihsnus gninrom thgirb eht tsniaga seye sih edahs ot
,dengiser dednuos rekraP ".wonk I"
pot eht morf sblub owT
.dehcaorppa yeht sa s'ybressap ot tuo gnillac saw
,yltnatcepxe draob eht dehctaw maS
.kcab dekool reven dna loohcS hgiH retfa ymedaca eht ot thgiarts enog d'ehs oehT ekiL
.seednetta gnimocni eht gnihctaw
,redluohs reh ot ti desiar ehs nehT
,ssarg eht no liat reh deppals maS
.taht ta ,woc a htiW" .dedihc rekraP
.rentrap txen ym ti gnikam fo gnikniht m'I .sknahT"
,maS dna racsO htob naht rellat teef eerht derewot taht snroh gnilruc htiw peehs nrohgib a
.teb taht edam I nehw poc a erew uoy togrof I
.sevooh gnipmolc sih rednu morf tuo teef reh peek ot gniyrt
.eciffo eht ni teiuq dna ecaep emos teg d'I neht tsael tA
,gnizama erom nevE
.yawdim eht fo gninnigeb eht ta detautis htoob tekcit tsesolc eht sdrawot regnif debbew a detniop ehS ".semag
.ssarg eht ni stovid elttil dnuor gnikam dnuorg eht ta dewap fooh kcab enO .deffuh racsO
,tnatsid saw noisserpxe siH
,putrats lacol a ta noitisop a ekat ot ocixeM weN morf dnaltroP ot devom d'eh taht reh dlot d'eh ,enilnO
.yrt rehtona no tsisni dluoc eh erofeb
.tellam a detceles racsO sa tsehc reh ot nooccar hsulp hsirag reh degguh dna dehgis maS
.reh ta deralg racsO nehw ffo tuc tub
.mih rof hguone doog saw ehs taht tbuod reh edam noissimda s'racsO
.sexob tah reh dedrager dna tesolc eht ot revo tnew ehS
.noitcelfer reh fo tnorf ni sserd a dleh ehs elihw
.rettis a meht tog ew ,yrrow t'noD"
.teb ruo now uoy ,esac yna nI
.erofeb naht eno rethgil dna rellams ylthgils a esohc eh tsael tA
:yojne esaelP   .egapbew sih no
.trihs pu nottub etihw sih fo cirbaf eht tsniaga llews ot selcsum eht gnisuac
,ruf s'maS delffur ezeerb nrehtron A
.sezirp muidem eht fo eno kcip nac uoy taht roF
,daehrevo dedilg sllugaeS
,flesmih sa llat sa tsomla
.uoy tuoba tol a em dlot s'ahtnamaS"
daeherof sih revo wol nwod dellup saw tI
",em fo nuf gnikam potS"
ecnef eht tsniaga dexaler nrohgnoL saxeT derruf-nat ehT
deretnab rekraP dna ehs elihW ".ti
,egdol reh ot ecnartne retawrednu eht hguorht evael naht rehtaR
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.uoy teem ot desaelp ,racsO"
.yltsenoh ,snooccaR
.ezirp tsellams eht niw uoy stegrat neves tih nac uoy fI"
.eno rehtona pu dekcip dna sserd eht deppord ehS
,kcab depmuj dna mra sih fo og tel maS
,puorg a sa revo deklaw yehT
.suoires noisserpxe sih ,deddon eH
",snoitacifitrec nogerO ym gnitteg hsinif I elihw won thgir naicinhcet bal a sa gnikrow m'I"
.sregnif sih hguorht detniuqs dna seye sih fo tnorf ni wap a dleh rekraP ".eciffo
,mih ta pu kool ot daeh reh dekcoc maS
.llub gib a s'eh skniht ereh ynit ,hO"
.meht sdrawot etalp eht gnitsurht ,dias eh
.gnihctiwt eson dna sreksihw sih ,dias rekraP
.ti tuoba saw taht
.tfeh dna thgiew sti htiw railimaf emoceb ot tnemom a koot dna ti detfil maS
.feiht eht morf walc raeb eht fo tser eht tcetorp ot deganam wohemos dah ycatS dna rekraP taht was ehs soahc eht nI
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.maS ta decnalg dna detatiseh racsO
.esuap a retfa dias eh
.hcaer reh fo tuo dna pu ti detsiwt dniw eht tub
.ruf reh fo eerf snip ybbob eht gniraet
".rekraP ,rentrap ym si siht ,racsO ,yawynA"
.ycatS ot etag eht yb gnignuol llub eht tuo gnitniop ,dias maS ",si eh erehT"
.yawdim eht otni deklaw yeht sa stekcit eht fo emos maS dednah racsO
.tsol ro yawa nwolb eb ot enorp dna sedir eht no lacitcarpmi eb dluow tah a tub