.snoitseuq sih htiw llor a no saw erus xaM
.erom fo ytilibissop eht gnireffo t’nsaw I ekil dednuos ti lausac os ton emit emas eht ta tub ,tlob t’ndluow eh taht hguone lausac dnuos ti ekam ot deirt I  ”.seirrow oN“
”-syek eht teg tsuj em tel
,yllautca piuq dab-flah a t’nsaw tI
.ettal rellik taht pu devres yllanif dah skcuBeulB smeeS .spil ym gnikcil
,em raen noitasrevnoc yreve tsomla raeh ot ton elbissopmi ti edam srae yffulf gib yM
.deunitnoc I sa yaw eht tuo ti gnipeek ,kcab sih revo liat sih dekcilf dna
”.pohs eeffoc ypparc a ni ti morf yawa flesruoy kcol toN
,pu dekool dna gnigassem deppots eH
,htoob eht morf tuo dils I
”.semit fo elpuoc tsal eht rO“
.)skoobe( skooB goD daB dna
.tsetorp dluoc xaM erofeb deppans eh
,resolc denael dna spil ym dekcil I
.enohp sih ta llits ,dehgis aneyh ehT
.keehc sih no elzzum ym gnitser
,rood eht ot em derehsu eh sa
”,netfo os ereh tuo gnah uoy yhw nialpxe t’nseod tahT“
,uoy no liab ot dneirf ruoy fo nettor smeeS
,tuo dlos stekcit eht lla erofeb setunim evif tuobA“ ”?taht s’yhW“
,gniod saw tahw revo lortnoc tsol I
.daeh sih koohs dna yawa dellup tsuj eh tub ,mih no nwod elzzum ym dehsup dna delwoy I ,dekrI
,neddih deyats I tub lamron ot denruter ylkciuq rettahc ehT
,enèT aL htiw dessesbo yllacitcarp s’ohw
,naom dna tnurg yreve ot gnidnopser
,pmur sih derimda dna kcab dellup I
.rehtruf og ot dah I
?yltneg nwod em gnittel eh sI
.yah fo llems thgil ,teews eht dna ,edisyrtnuoc eht fo llems tnatsid eht ,htrae eht
.retnuoc lanif eht nwod gnipiw ,delbmum eh
”!pu naelc em pleh dna enohp ruoy ta gnirats potS !eduD“
.ylthgit esroh eht degguh neht ,yltfos gnihtemos dias aneyh ehT
noisiced ym edam I
”-ot tuoba saw I wonk uoy tel evah dluohs I“
”.xof ,uoy stius tcerid gnieB“
.nwo ym htiw level emac daeh sih sa gnittauqs ,nwod tneb eH
,selcric debbur ylwols dna
,swap ym ni ti htiw tuo deklaw dna
”,sretnuoc eht hcaer ot hguone llat ton er’uoY“
,yrruFoS rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY .ruF htiw sdoG dna
.noitseuq a naht noitpmussa na erom secnereferp ym
.no swap rieht teg dluoc sremotsuc hcni erauqs yreve hcum ytterp ,sriahc ,selbat
.taht tuoba etirw ,efil ecneirepxE
…drac tfig a ,ygolopa lamrof a ,eeffoc eerf a gnireffo
.kcab sih dehctarcs dna
thginot tub pu-em-kcip gnineve rieht gnitteg sruf lanrutcon fo elkcirt a eb d’ereht yllausU
?kcoc a fo retsnom taht htiw ffo deracs neeb yeht dah semit ynam woH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”?enim ro mrod ruoY“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.erom hcuM .erom detnaw I
.pu em ekow srae gnihctiwt yM
.kcab ym dniheb liat ym dehsiws dna
?ot gniklat eh saw ohW
.ecnats sih gninetfos ,delims eh
seye ym gnibbur dna srae ym gnippolf
.retnuoc a no gninael ,desiar liat
.remotsuc a ekil em ot gnikaeps pots d’eh gnipoh
”?laer neve srebmun eht erA
.moorerots a otni dna
?drah os siht saw yhW
.yrotciv ni ylippah liat sih gnihsiws ,detrons eH
.dnim ni dah I tahw gniredisnoc ,eno siht htiw dael eht ekat ot gnivah dnim t’ndid I
- saw tnaem I tahW .yrroS“
:tnecs sih fo ffins a teg dluoc I yllaniF
”.ti wonk uoy erofeb revo eb lliw inU
,dnuora denrut dna mih ta dekniw I .dehsulb xaM
.71:02 .hctaw ym ta dekool I
;mottob eht no eno eht neeb syawla d’I
aneyh ehT .yek tcerroc eht rof gnihsif
”?erus tnecrep derdnuh a uoY“
delggiw I !tfihs gnisolc eht ekat ot gnireetnulov mih draehrevo I nehw ,neht esirprus ym enigamI
,llit eht no pu tas eH
,sgel rednels ,sknalf yvruc
”?hteet ym htiw uoy hctac I diD ?gnorw s’tahW“
,liat sih htiw gniyalp ot kcab tnew I
.hguone dias srae sih ni poord eht tub
”,thgif a tnaw t’nod I .xaM ,kooL“
”?cilbup eht htiw gnikrow peek llits uoy od htrae no woH“
.lavorppa ni fooh a depmats dna deinnihw eH
.noillats onimolap keels a
.liat ym dehsiws I sa lived a ekil gninnirg ,deksa I
”?taht ekil etirw uoy yllufepoH“
,detrons dna spih sih no sdnah sih decalp eH
.mih nopu dedneped noitavlas esohw etyloca deiznerf a ekil mih depihsrow dna ,swap ym htiw kcoc sih fo esab eht dezeeuqs
.rehtruf yna ti ekat t’ndid eh tub ,dehgis eH
.suoires saw eh wohs ot gnitaropave elims
,tnemom a rof desuap I
,nuf emos evah ot deen tsuj uoy tub
.saw I trohs woh nevig gniddon ylerab daeh sih
- llew gniog ton saw siht esuaceb
.nihc ym htaenrednu ruf eht gnilffur ,derekcin eh
.enola eb ot tnaw t’ndid I tub
,yadrutaS dneps ot ecalp elbirret a saw tI
.og dluow ti thguoht I woh t’nsaw sihT
.yltcefrep taoc nedlog sih detnemilpmoc hcihw enam etihw yppolf a htaenrednu tuo doots seye eulb siH .smra mils
.ta gnitteg saw eh tahw wenk I
”.tihs ekil setsat syawla eeffoc eht ,ton ro naelc si ecalp eht fi ecnereffid a sekam ti ekiL !llihC“ ”-em sa emas eht yltcaxe diap gnitteg er’uoY“
.retnuoc eht dniheb gnivid ,deremmats eh
,ecnedifnoc ni pu ruf ym deffulf I
,wap eno ni puc eht dleh I
”.eb ot esle erehwemos evah ylbaborp uoy - xof ,re ,he tuB“
.ekoms htiw niarb ym gnildda
detaeper I ”.yako s’tI“
.thgirpu flesym dellup dna desruc I
,enam sih ta dellup dna eerios eht tuoba gnihtemos delbmum eH
,sdnif gnibrutsid fo tsil a ffo gnilttar erofeb enam sih koohs dna dekoj eH
”?nwo ruoy no eganam ll’uoy erus uoy
.edisni tuoba hsols muc sih gnileef
.em ta nwod gnikool
.hsup a dedeen ylniatrec eh
htaerb peed a koot eH
.ti ssim ot detnaw eno oN
,nwod dna pu em ta gnikool ,dnuor denrut eH
.enot sih derongi I
.su neewteb noisnet eht fo emos desuffid ti tsael ta tub
.daeh daorb sih revo pu gnivom erofeb yltneg gnippal
,daeh ym revo norpa sih dekcilf dna dennirg I
.rood eht dekcol dna dehgis eH
,slangiS tnedissiD ,taeH sa hcus
,mottob elbapac a saw I elihw ,sediseB
.norpa sih rof gnihcaer ,dehgis eh ”,yrroS“
”.elbisivni leef t’nod ew os s’ti ebyaM .eniF“
,revo dettort dna dehgis xaM
,wap sih tuo kcuts dna dennirg eH
,ecnad eht ta no neddort liat ym teg ton ot llams ooT
neht dna ,pu rehto hcae ezis ,srenil-eno fo elpuoc a egnahcxe d’ew thguoht I
.edisni deregnil taht rezirodoed dna
.tohsrevo d’eh erehw sretnuoc eht nwod nar sepor kciht lareves elihw
.edistuo elkcac tfos eht dna rood a fo gnimmals eht yb gnigduj ,dessim eH
.tsiser t’ndid eH
”.ris ,taht raeh ot dah uoy yrros m’I“
.hturt eht eb ot evisnefed oot tuo emac ti tub
”.enoemos dnif ll’uoy ylekil erom eht ,ksa uoy erom ehT“
.srae ym fo spit eht no
.yawa egde eht gnikat noitatiseh ym
,sgniht teews devol I tub
.swalc ym htiw puc eht gnikop
eloh sih tsniaga bmuht ym desserp I
.eniuqe yltcnitsid saw ynihw dehctip-hgih ehT
,norpa sih deitnu ,retnuoc eht ffo depmuj eH
”,oot kcuf-tnecs laer a s’ti esoppus I“
.xof a fo tuo rewsna thgiarts a teg ot elbissopmi eb ot tnaem saw tI
.tnaem eh tahw rehtona dna
.stnap ym nwod dellup yllausnes
,ylwolS .ytlas yltniaf
.gniht ’seiceps ym t’nera seitrap giB“
’nabru‘ ,delttes ,larebil eht sa
.htoob eht morf pu gnikop llits srae ym
.ezis ym fo esuaceb em gnikoolrevo syawla erew elpoeP
.ylideen esrup elohliat sih gnihctaw
.gnignol dna ,tnemeticxe
.elzzum ym ni etsat ruos a tfel dna hcti srae ym edam kcabdeef riehT
,tleb sih htiw delbmuf dna pu dehcaer I
,noitingocer ni derekcilf seye sih sa dehctaw I
.roiretni pohs sseletsat a ni devres eeffoc ercoideM
.’ecivda‘ rieht tuoba derac yllautca I ekil kool dna ereh tis ot dah I tnaem hcihW
.tihsllub ecivres remotsuc taht lla ni rehtona ot gnikaeps tneduts a raeh ot driew os tsuj saw tI
.ssalc gnitirw ym fo esuaceb skcuBeulB ot emac I ,yllanigirO
,tfahs sih fo htgnel eht nwod dna pu dekcil
.elttil a evil ot uoy tnaw tsuj I
.srae ym gnikcilf ,dekaeuqs I
.rettalc a htiw su dniheb erehwemos ti gnissot ,tleb sih deppilcnu dna dennirg I
.denruter I nehw deksa xaM ”?lleW“
!liat ym gnitsiwt saw erus eH
,em sdrawot delleviws seye sa taes ym ni nwod knurhs I
.em sdrawot delias ti sa lrufnu did norpa eht dna ,strops ta doog reven saw I ecnefed ym nI
.yawa em evig t’ndluow yeht os kcab srae ym gniyalps ,renroc eht dnuora dekaep dna htoob ym otni kcab dekcud I
.dehgual aneyh eht
.ffo dehsinif eh sa gnikcilf srae sih ,detnurg eh
.ecaf ym ssorca gnillup tpek elims eht tub ,evom txen ym tuoba kniht dna etartnecnoc ot deirt I
eht gnittel ,stnemom fo elpuoc a rof ssensselpleh dengief dna dnuora delbmuf I
,daeh sih htaenrednu tuo eugnot ym dleh I
.egdub t’ndid aneyh eht tub
”.eerf rof eeffoc rieht meht evig uoY“
”.ssem a etiuq edam ew kniht I“
ti otni spord fo elpuoc tsrif eht gnixaoc
,issaveleT yb ”skcuBeulB“ si
.ebul sa krow thgim taht gnihtyna rof moorerots eht tuoba gnikool flesym dnuof I dna
,daeh sih htiw pu ti denil dna puc yawaekat a debbarg I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,desuap ,detrons xaM
”,ssab eht dnats ot evitisnes oot
,denimreted tlef I erom eht
.maebnus a ni gniksab ,htoob ym otni kcab delggiw I
”,ytrap eht rof raey txen syawla s’erehT“
”.pleh emos htiw od dluoc uoY“
.enohp sih morf pu gnikool neve ylerab ,detrons aneyh eht
.evif litnu nepo t’ndid rab supmac eht dna paehc trid saw eeffoc eht tub
.erusopmoc sih ta yvne htiw dellif saw I rewsna ym rof ylmlac os gnitiaw
,won ylivaeh gnihtaerb saw xaM
,llews htaehs ym edam
,spil ym tsniaga tsurht eh sa pu em tuhs eH
”,tcerid os gnieb llits er’uoy raeh ot dooG“ .dehsulb I
.lufetarg saw I ecno rof dna maerdyad ym fo tuo em dellup eeffoc elbirret ym fo etsat ehT  ...nwo
.gninaelc ot kcab gnitteg yb flesmih gniysub ,ffo mih dehsup dna
deffuh eH ”!og tsuJ“
”.emit eht flah ni enod eb ll’eW“
!enola eb ot desoppus saw eH
.evisserpmi saw tnuoma ehT
.erots eht pu dekcol eh sa ttub eht no em deppals dna em dessik eH
”.pohs eeffoc ypparc a ni yawa dekcol devil era sevil ruo fo tsom - hu
.aneyh eht retfa htolc tew a gniworht ,deppans eH ”!oG“
.tfahs sih nwod gnilbbird erp kcils taht lla htiw neve ,em edisni teg ot elba eb dluow eh taht yaw on saw erehT
”?xof a htiw ti enod reve uoy evaH“
su ekam ot gniog saw I
.duorhs a ekil em revo depard dna em fo pot no llef ti ,yletarucca erom ro ,ti thguac I
.ruf sih ni sthgilhgih knip mug elbbub htiw aneyh depirts a ta gnitniop
,yltnangidni kcab srae ym dekcilf dna tnemom a koot I
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.htaerb peed a koot dna spil ym dekcil I
.tsiaw sih ot pu dehcaer srae ym fo spit eht fi neve
”,thginot rof etad on tog ev’uoy esuaceb worromot gniod ylno er’uoy wonk htob ew ,no emoc hO“
,dedivorp noitadommoccA seicepS tnedutS spmal-taeh eht no dehctiws dna mrod ym ot kcab knuls ev’dluoc I cennef a gnieB
.erutcip a deppans I muc sih yawa epiw dluoc eh erofeb tub ,slewot repap emos debbarg dna
delbmarcs eh sa gnirettalc sevooh ,depmuj eH ”-yeH“
,tenalPruF hguorht elbaliava seigolohtna ni ro
- sgniht fo tsil a tuo delttar eH
.ecivda s’aneyh taht fo tnuocca no eert gnorw eht pu gnikrab tsol teg mih ekil noillats etuc a tel t’ndluoc I ,tuo krow t’ndid gnineve siht fi nevE
.smra sih dedlof dna seye sih dellor eH ”…erus ,haeY“
,tnelis deniamer dna liat sih dekcilf esroh ehT
.kcals mih tuc dna wols og d’I esruoc fo os
.kcoc gniniarts sih tsniaga elzzum ym fo pit eht gnihsurb
.noissimda taht  revo ssolg dluoc I gnihsiw ,delbmum I
.00:02 ta desolc yeht litnu enola lla eb d’eh
”...etad a tog uoy fi uoy rof revoc d’eh yas did eH“
htaerb mraw sih leef dluoc I taht hguone esolc saw eH
?pot tneced a eb I dluow
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.eugnot sih dleh eh sa gniltsirb ruf sih
,tnemssarrabme ni gninrub t’nerew srae ym fI
.ecaf s’xaM ni enohp sih devohs dna dekrims aneyh ehT
”?txen od ot em tnaw uoy od tahw oS“
.yltneg ttub yxes sih gnittap ,mih dehsuh I
,dah d’I skcuf gniyfsitasnu eht lla hguorht kcab dehsalf dnim yM
.won tuoba detrats yllausu tfihs siH
,ti dias yllautca eh esilaer owt dnoces a em koot tI  ”!kcuF“
,mih dniheb riahc eht decalp I sa tnemegaruocne ni spih sih delggiw eH
”?rebmun s’dneirf aneyh ruoy s’tahW“ .ezorf eH
.driew elttil a tlef ti tsenoh eb oT
.revo ti gnissot ,desigolopa eh
.esnepsus lufyalp ni mih gnipeek
,wols ot gnitrats saw gnihtaerb siH
.elims yrw ym nruter ot gniyrt
”.gninrom eht ni pu gninaelc syojne eh epoh I“ .delims neht
00:91 morf dna ,werc noteleks a ot nwod tnew pohs eht 00:81 tA
.ettal rellik a pu devres
,sevren ym hguorht gninrub erised
eh sa sevruc kniwt esoht gnitnualf mih denigami I
.mih morf tuo gnippird erp fo daeb elbazis a
.elzzup eht fo eceip gninioj eht mih evag ydob ym sa pu gnithgil
!gnisolc tsap tpels d’I
.enod krow yna gnitteg ton ylraelc dna
”?thginot rebmun s'yug etuc emos uoy teg ot em tnaw uoY“
.erus rof nwo ruo no eb d’ew tnaem ngis ylno ffats eht dna ,swodniw yna morf yawa erew ew ereh kcaB
- tfihs txen ruoy revoc ll’I ,etad a llup nac uoy em ot evorp nac uoy fi ,tahw uoy lleT“
.ruf ruo tsuj ot nwod teg
,dees sih htiw mir eht ot dellif saw puc eeffoc ehT
.eugolaid etirw ot woh aedi on dah I dias llits ssalc eht tub
!xes ot semoc ti nehw lufecruoser ton era sexof taht dias eb reven ti
.yrd mih otni tsurht ot gniog t’nsaw I
,mih ot resolc pots a koot dna delims I
.em nees t’ndah xaM gnipoh
”?esroh a - htiw - ti enod - reve uoY“
,saw eh tfos woh gnikool morf llet tsuj dluoc I
”,gnimmir morf tsuj ffo tog uoy taht toh adnik s’tI“
.stroffe ym detsiser daeh nellows sih tub ,mih ekat ot deirt dna dluoc I sa ediw sa htuom ym denepo I
”,evitisnes os saw ssa esroh wonk t’ndid I“
!gnicitne ro yxes t’nsaw tahT
”.enoyna teem ot yaw elbirret a ti sekam hcihw …tuo enoyna kcip ot elbissopmI“ .dennirg I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
gniyojne ,deilper I ”,eniM“
”-ereh elihw a em ekat llits ll’tI“
.hguorht dezeeuqs I sa shgiht sih tsniaga pu gnihsurb yletarebiled srae
.ogol eht no kcub eulb etuc eht yllaicepse
tonk ym gnizeeuqs liat ydeen taht fo thguoht ehT
.suolaej tsuj erew yehT
.yawyna dne esool a ta m’I“
-edisni tuoba ti gnikcilf
.nwo ym tsniaga eil ydob sih gnivah
skcuBeulB sdrow 0093 tuobA:yojne esaelP
,detrons xaM  .delggig I
-mih htiw emoc ot em gninokceb dna ngis gninepo eht dnuora sehctiws dna skniw eH
”.laer ytterp saw dah tsuj uoy tnemugra tahT“
.tsethgils eht ni mih tnuom ot deganam t’ndah I taht deirrow t’nsaw I .dennirg I
yrots s’yadoT dna
.riahc a barg ot moorerots eht fo tuo dekcud I ”.melborp a toN“
.esae ta mih tup d’ti gnipoh
,won desolc er’eW !ris yrroS“  .kcab
”?spohs eeffoc dna sretirw htiw ti si tahW“
”.srettam ffuts siht fo enoN“
,em ot esolc deyats tsuj eH
,deggurhs I ”,aedi oN“
.sesroh tuoba dias yeht tahw eurt saw tI
”,yadot uoy htiw no etirw ot gnihtyna gnirb yltcaxe t’ndid uoy tub ,lleW“
,5102 ecnis snoitacilbup yrruf suoirav ni dehsilbup neeb sah dna
”,haey hO“ .deilper eh
.rab eht ta sknird redro ot murcs eht ni em tsap egrab d’ohw seno eht ekil yklub t’nsaw eH
,eugnot ym dleh dna gnihton dias I
.rood nepo eht tuo yaw ym ekam ot gnisufer
.draobpuc a ni paeh delpmurc a ni ti devohs dna
.llits liat ym peek ot gniyrt
,detartsurf er’uoy wonk I“ .seye htob htiw esroh eht ta kool dluoc eh os yawa egnirf knip sih gnihsurb ,dehgis aneyh eht
,elkcuhc mih draeh I sa dehctiwt srae yM
”,rehtie thginot eb ot erehwyna tog yltcaxe t’nevah I“
- boj ruoy tsol uoy fi erac t’ndluow uoY“
”,od ew tsellams eht s’tI“
,ylregae gniffins ,ssa sih tsniaga pu elzzum ym denil I
”,sdneirf ym emag srebmun a s’tI“
”!gnikaeps yllacirohpateM-rE“ .parC .denworf eH
.elims a htiw ytingidni sih gningief
,ti dekoocrevo d’I thguoht I tnemom a roF
,detrons noillats ehT
.enam ym ni dniw eht teg dna tuo og d’I ,uoy erew I fI“
.tiaw em edam dna ereht doots eH
.00:61 ta detrats tfihs siH
eeffoc fo llems dirca ,gnorts eht yawa welb ria hserf ehT
?mih htiw yah eht ni elssut ot detnaw yletarepsed I taht
.em kootrevo tsul eruP
,ti tuoba thguoht I erom ehT
.elggiw dna hctiwt mih gnileef
,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ saw sihT.tcerid os gnieb
.pool-kcen eht ni tonk a deit dna sretnuoc eht htaenrednu morf norpa na tuo dellup eh litnu
.mih dniheb retnuoc eht gnippirg ,dehtaerb eh
”,esle gnihtemos yrt ,hu ,ew …tuoba woH“
,snoitacilbuP LAOG ,flowafoS
.edistuo ksud saw ti dna ,enog dah maebnus ehT .derevihs I
.tsehc eht no noillats ykniwt eht dettap eH
.revo erew sgniht detcepxe eh ekil kcab htaerb sih gnitteg no desucof eH
.tsehc ralucsum naht ssel s'aneyh eht ni regnif sih deirub eH
.ria eht gnillif slacimehc gninaelc fo llems dna yarps fo hsoocs tfos eht
”.meht evres uoy nehw rebmun s’lrig a teg neve t’nac uoY“
,pot a flesym deredisnoc reven d’I ,liat ym yB
”-ytrap eht ta xof etuc a dnif nac I fi ees ll’I“
sretnuoc eht dniheb em del esroh ehT
”.enod tnemngissa gnitirw emos teg ot dah I ,sediseB“ .deggurhs I
.reve naht dekan erom gnileef em tfel dna trapa em deleep dah sdrow sih daetsnI
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.nalp eht fo trap t’nsaw tfihs gninaelc a no wap a gnidnel fi neve ,ytinummoc eht otni mih emoclew ot ,yag
.elttil a evil t’nod uoy fi flesruoy etah ll’uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”,pleh ruoy rof sknahT“
.tuo gnillips sevren
,teews yltsom saw eH
,sgel nepo sih neewteb dekcud dna
.mih dniheb gnihsiws liat
tpecxe gnihtyreve otni troffe na hcus tup tnioj eeffoc ysuol a hcus taht gnisirprus saw tI
sedutitalp kaeps ot deunitnoc esroh ehT
.tops elbatrofmoc erom a dnif ot gniyrt ,htoob eht tsniaga kcab
.suoegartuo ,wonk I
.eporg lufyalp a htiw
.tcefrep saw sihT !liat ym yB
- mih ot kcab tcejbus eht egnahc ot dehsiw I
.deugnot-revlis yllarutan gnieb
.erom neve teb eht ekam ot tnaw em edam tnemom siht fo llirht eht tey dna
.sevren htiw ykahs elttil a saw eciov yM
.hgis detnioppasid sih ot ecitcarp fo ria tcnitsid a saw erehT
.em llems mih gnittel
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rewsna na rof on ekat ot gniog t’nsaw eh tub
.tnemeticxe ni dekael eh sa snaej s’xaM no demrof tops pmad A
.norpa sih dniheb gnipoleved eglub suoiruc a
puc dellif eht rof dil a debbarg I
.yddig em tfel tnecs ehT
.aedi na em evag ti tsael ta dna
”.mih rof gnitiaw dnuora tis tsuj uoy fi evol ni llaf reve t’now uoY“
,msaisuhtne sih dellangis dna detrons esroh eht sa hcum sa dna ,gnihtyna eb ot mees t’ndid erehT
.duht eltneg a htiw elzzum eht no em dekcams dna tuo deppop kcoc sih ,stnap sih denottubnu I nehW
,kcab ym dniheb derepsihw yeht ,egatnavda riafnu na dah sexoF
”.teb taht niw uoy pleh ot tnaw I“ .ti dias I oS
,denway-ekaf I ”.yako s’tI“
,a fo erom m’I ,mU“
.seye sih ffo enam sih gniworht ,detrons xaM
”.gninaelc nehw dnif ew tihs eht fo emos eveileb t’ndluow uoY“ .eeffoc sti
,thgir saw
dnuor nups d’eh erofeB
,mih revo selcric ni eugnot ym nar I
.steliot eht ni yksirf oot yaw tog elpuoc a emit eno gnidulcni
dna tleb ym delkcubnu I sa liat ym ni yaws eht gnipeek
- hturt eht dias I fi yawa mih elbmag ot gniog saw I ekil leef ti did yhW
.citsimitpo t’nsaw I tub ,ni dekcol neeb t’ndah I yllufepoH
,ettal ym desrun I
tsud eht ni fooh sih dewap eh ”…oS“
,yawa gnipeews detrats dna
.erom rof kcab tnew dna dennirg I
.ylteiuq ekops dna resolc denael aneyh ehT ”.dleif eht yalp
,trapa sgel sih daerps dna dnuora denrut eh sa smra sih ni daeh sih gnidih
.das dna nedlog seye
,xof a saw I esuaceb em gnigduj ssalc ym fo raey eritne na htiw pu tup d’I
.remotsuc etiruovaf sih
.pu debmilc I sa roolf eht otno gnikael kcoc sih
.em ta pu selzzum rieht denrut yeht yaw eht ni ti ees dluoc I
.tuo dennalp lla ti dah I .ytilaer a
,derevihs I .yllaniF
.dedarg puorg saw tnemngissa lanif eht tub ,mret eritne eht rof ruf ym gnilkcirp tuohtiw meht derongi d’I
.taeh eht deruovas I sa pu deffulf ruf yM
,krow ot tog I .hA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
enohp sih ta yawa gnippat
,mih htaenrednu erp fo elddup eht gnittopS
*** .tiaw saw od ot dah I llA
.skcuBeulB   issaveleT yB
-mih llems neve dluoc I
.em deppots dna nwod dehcaer eh sa yltfos gninihw
:xaM was I nehw tihsllub rieht llac ot tuoba saw I
.pu nekow tsuj d’I fi sa
,hguoht euc ym dessim eH
tel tuB .rellik doom laer a eb d’tahT
moorb a debbarg esroh ehT
.eurt lla saw taht tsael tA .dehgis I
.mih revo eugnot ym nar ylwols I erofeb
.tops evitisnes a desaet I revenehw hctiwt gnir sih gnihctaw deyojne I yned t’ndluoc I tub
.mih morf llef ti sa erp fo pord a gnihctac
.pis a koot I sa ylippah gniggaw liat
.eugnot ym dekips noitcejer fo raef ehT
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.em dniheb tuoba liat ym gnihsiws ,desaet I
.emit siht serised ym tuoba yrots a etirw ot gniog t’nsaw I
,mih esol ot gniog saw I ekil pu doots ruf ym fo dnarts yrevE
”,ees I kcaberab gnidiR“
.no norpa eht tup I erofeb mrahc deruonoh-emit sti od tca cennef ynit etuc
”.ris ,enif eb ll’I“
.deremmats eh ”,ereh ton ebyaM“
.moorb a debbarg d’I
”.ytrap eht morf revognah a gnisrun er’uoy elihw worromot gninepo ruovaf a uoy gniod m’I“
.spih ym ni yaws tsethgils eht gnidda dna liat ym gniggaw yltnalahcnon ,deilper I
?meht llac uoy nehw ylper a teg reve uoy oD“
,flesym detressa I
dehgis eH ”.pu siht naelc ot deen ot gniog m’I …revewoH“
,htiw detrilf neve d’eh yug tsrif eht saw ylbaborp I
,puc eht ni dnal pord retfa pord draeh I sa gninnirg
.lwoy yxof a sa tuo emac ti fo laed doog a tpecxe ,dehgis I
.su revo tpews ria thgin looc eht sa nepo rood eht gnidloh ,denworf eH
,detrons-flah eh
,leef d’ti lufrednow woh tuoba kniht em edam hcihw
”.llac liat a no m’I fi neve
.tsiaw sih tsap emac ylerab srae esohw cennef a ton tub ,noillats rehtona htiw dnuora gniyalp erew eh fi ebyaM
,htaerb yreve no tsomla gnitrons
”,oot ti rof yap ym teg ll’uoY“
,mih wollof ot em denokceb eh sa gnileef eht dellepsid ylkciuq tuB .won erew yeht
.ezeeuqs a kcoc kciht sih gnivig ,deltsihw I
,ytisoiruc fo sdnarts tsetniaf eht htiw devaewretni sevren
.epytoerets eht ot pu evil ot detnaw I emit siht tub
,mih htaenrednu pu eugnot ym dekcilf I
?taht mih dlot I dah yhW
purys allinav yltsom saw tI
.eerioS remmuS saw thginoT
”?enim ro mrod ruoy ni kcuf rehtar d’uoY“
.hguoht mih rof hcum oot tib a saw tI
.mih gnirewsna ,daeh ym koohs I
,ertnec eht tsniaga eugnot ym gnihsup ,selcric ni tunod sih dnuora eugnot ym gninnur
:ekil-reed erom saw eH
.detresed eb d’ti
,detrons esroh eht
”,gniog erew yeht dias eno on
”,ssa laer a er’uoY“
”!yenom eht deen yllautca I
.daeh ym dnuora gnihsur doolb fo dnuos eht revo mih raeh ylerab dluoc I tub
”...gnineve lla tog ev’uoy fI“
”...ytic eht ni stra enif yduts ot gniog er’uoy meht llet uoy nehw dad & mom morf troppus eht teg ot dnet t’nod em ekil sesroh larur ,ynnikS“ .detrons eH
,niaga ffo deliart eh ”…llew
.erom rof yrgnuh dna yddig em gnivael nuf gnidnepmi eht
”.krow ot gniog ton tsuj s’ti ,on oN“
”.peelsa eb llits ylbaborp d’I tnemugra ruoy rof t’nsaw ti fI“
.dneirf ruoy m’I ,eduD“
,em evres ot revo sdneb eh sa sbbob liat bun siH
”.slrig ot klat ot woh gninrael emit dneps dluoc uoy ,stfihs ynam os gnikat deppots uoy fI“