.tohs a htrow saw ti ,yaw rehtiE
,sruoh rof pal reh ni mih htiw tis dna lliswodniw eht ot pu elbat rennid eht morf riahc nedoow a llup dluow ehS
.tbuod on ,dezylana ecnamrofrep sih dna
.suoregnad oot saw ti esuaceb ,epat noituac ni depparw saw erutcurts yalp eht tub
.eugra dluoc eh erofeb pu gnuh neht dna ,dias I
.dik a saw I nehw gnimmalc og ot desu ew erehw stalfdum eht no edit wol ekil
”,uoy thguat I ecnis elihw a neeb s’tI
”?onicippup a tnaw uoy od“ ,dias I
”.snevar evah ylno ew kniht I“ .desuap eH
”?hguoht ,gnihtyna htiw od ot evah snevar eht od tahW .taerG“
dneterp ot gniunitnoc naht rehto
,cilobmys erom saw llems eht fi ro ,gniyd saw eh fi erus t’nsaw I .htaed ekiL
reganeet detalosi-yllaicos a tuoba levon a no gnikrow yltnerruc si ohw
,gnikeirhs fo tibah a dah eH
.saw ehs gnorw woh ezilaer ot mom ym teg dluoc I yaw eno ylno saw ereht wenk I
”.derif teg ot tnaw t’nod I .tsuj I“
nwod depoows worc ehT
,krap eht deyevrus I
”,sgnirts evah t’nod straeH“
,raey roines ym fo retsemes lanif eht gnirud tniop emos tA  adoC yb
,efil ot delworg enigne ehT
dah eH .seloh fo lluf dna ybbacs erew srae derettat ,trohs sih dna
tsuj eH .god a s’eh esimorp I“
,gnilgnad hsael ,pu gnilcric saw ti nehT
tsigoloib dna retirw noitcif a ,adoC yb
sa mih ot derrefer syawla ehS
.retnuoc eht rednu morf tuo rehtaf ym gnidael ,dias I ”,god ym si ereH“
,kaeb sih dekcilc eH
tsisni ot nageb osla ehS
,dias ehs ,gnippohs yrecorg eht od ot gnivah syawla tuoba denialpmoc I nehW
.god taht llik ot dah I
.rebmemer I esruoc fo ,no emoC“ .dias eh
.drawrofthgiarts erom neeb tsuj evah dluohs I ebyaM
.etaf sih detpecca d’eh ekil
.etalocohc dna enieffac ot evitisnes yrev era sgod taht tcaf eht fo dednimer saw I tub
.won mih llik ylerus dluow enO
.edisni gniog tuohtiw redro nac uoy erehw wodniw a sah taht esuoh ruo morf raf ton pohs eeffoc a s’erehT
.god elttil elbirroh siht otni dad ym denrut mom ym
,enola mih teg ot elba neeb d’I semit wef ehT
.enif saw gnihtyreve gnidneterp tpek tsuj mom ym taht saw
.elgae na fo ezis eht ,worc eguh a saw
.yad toh a eb ot gniog saw ti tnaem taht ti ni remmihs fo dnik eht dah yks eht tub
”.worc a er'uoy erus ytterp m’I
si yrots s’yadoT dna
?kcits evird ot woh rebmemer uoY“
.sdneirf eb ot ton gnidiced erew ew nehw noitasrevnoc eht ni ,em dlot nosaJ dneirf-xe ym
,yawyna ti detsil I tub
.pu rehtaf ym dekcip dna
.tbed saw egelloc retfa krow rof noitacifilauq ylno ym tnaem hcihw
.mih erutluc ot rO
.pu mih rettub ot yaw tcefrep
.dluoc ehs ekil timmoc t’ndluoc I .yzal oot saw I
.gnihtoN“ .delims I
.enohporcim ynit a deciton I dna
,wed htiw tew llits saw ssarg ehT
.rehto hcae ot rood txen thgir devil d’eW
,rehgih dna rehgih
,elatyriaf a ekil ,fi ,derednow em edisni dlihc ehT
.nwod swodniw eht deknarc eW
.eid ot detnaw dna ,oot ,emoceb d’eh tahw detah eh ebyaM
.detneler eh ,yllaniF
.efil laer ni sahcom devol dah dad yM
.em ees t’ndluoc eh hguoht
sih gnikorts ,reveohw ro ztsiL ro nipohC ot gninetsil
,dias eh ”,ycilop wen a s’tI“
”.tuo og ot sdeen rehtaf ruoY“
.toof ym htiw retnuoc eht rednu mih dehsup I ,deredro I sA
.god nmad siht llik neve t’ndluoc I
.yltalf ,dias I ”?yhW“
,saw ti fi ro ,dad ym yllaer t’nsaw god eht wenk I
,sgnilbmar rehto dna ,tra
.gnola deyalp I os ,hguone ecin demees eH
”.ruoh na ekil ni ereht eb nac I
ecap ylerusiel a ta emoh deklaw I
.yas ot gniyrt m’I lla s’tahT .evisluper saw eH
.straeh evah RH taht decnivnoc ton osla m’I
.dias I ”,yeH“  .derewsna I
,roolf eht no saw eh ereht ,emoh kcab devom I nehw taht si wonk I llA
yojne esaelP  yffuwaes@
,dias I ”,sdneirf er’eW“
,rehtie boj a evah t’ndid ehs tub ,thgir saw ehS
.seog ti woh wonk uoy ,rehtona ot del gniht eno tub ,t’ndluow I mih derussa I
.em ni ti evah yllaer t’ndid I wenk I tub
,kaerb citohcysp nwo ym gnivah deredisnoc I
.god a otni demrofsnart neeb dah eh fi
”dliW eb ot nroB“
.yhw yas t’ndluoc I hguoht ,taorht ym ni pmul a saw erehT
.ti ekil dellems eh os dna ,htaed fo tnega na saw eh taht
”.hguoht noitseuq a evah I
,emuser a no doog kool t’nseod tbeD
retal setunim wef a dna ,tfel eH
t’nod uoY“ ”.uoy knahT
.trid desufni-ahcom fo sknuhc dewollaws dna dewehc erutaerc ylgu eht sa
”.pu dekcuf s’tahT“
,deddon I ”.uoy etah yllaer t’nod I“ ”.haeY“
.thguoht I ,gnihtyna ta doog neeb reven d’I
dedrocer gnieb saw eH
”.flowneppetS ot gninetsil rac a llats dluoc eno oN
,llems eht thguac eh ecno tub ,doog yrev eb ot mees t’ndid noisiv siH
erutcurts eht fo tniop tsehgih eht ta dehcreP
”.sehsid ruoy hsaw t’ndid uoy taht tespu si rehtaf ruoY“
,skeew txen eht revO
.maerc deppihw htiw deppot saw tI
.em ta derats ti yaw eht
?pleh taht seoD .edistuo og t’nac ehs os ,delppirc s’ehS .emoh ta god rehtona evah I“ .dias I ”,kool yeH“
.seye sih ni nettog dah maerc eht fo emos ebyaM
.retteb wonk d’I ecneics retupmoc ni derojam d’I fi ebyam tub ,gnihtemos ro yenom tuo tihs dna snoitacilppa boj tae
.srehtaef kcalb ynihs sih gnineerp tuoba tnew neht
”.god a yletinifed s’tI“
.maerc deppihw ni derevoc pu gnidne ecaf elohw sih
.taes regnessap eht ni tas worc ehT  .dliW eb ot nroB
.mih hsinup ot gniyrt saw ehs ebyaM
.mih rof dab tlef yleniuneg I
,ekans yrgna na ekil ,esion gniltsihw dehctip hgih ,suounitnoc fo tros a ekam dluow eh
,knats eh ,lla fo tsroW
”?uoy od ,boj a evah t’nod uoy ,lleW“
.rehtaf ym saw erutaerc cinomed taht
.ytic eht ssorca yaw eht lla
.no og ot mih rof detiaw I  ”.yeH“
.neercs eht no detanimulli eman s’nosaJ dneirf ym was I ,tuo ti koot I nehW
.suoreneg gnieb yltsenoh si god a mih gnillaC
,wodniw taht tuo gnikool devol ehS
.klaw lausu sih no rehtaf ym koot I ,gninrom txen ehT
,taht tuoba gnihtyna dnif t’ndluoc I
.sdneirf rehto on dah ew taht osla dna ,rehto hcae detah yllautca ew taht denrael lla d’ew
.tekcop ym ni gnizzub enohp ym tlef I
,pal reh ni cisum eht ot gninetsil saw eh nehw tub
.erom yna ti ees t’ndluoc I
,hserf llits saw ria ehT
.sgniw revo dniw fo dnuos ehT
,ssarg eht ta dekcil dna delworg eH
.emoclew er’uoy dnA .yrros yas ot evah
.noisserpxe deniarts a htiw em ta daeh sih gnikcoc ,dias eh
niks hsiulb htiw ,thgils saw eH
taht smargorp retupmoc nettirw ylpmis evah seinapmoc tsom ,tniop siht ta ,kniht I
.enimsaj dna leseid ekil dellems ria remmus ylrae ehT
.mom ym htiw od ot sah tI“ .dehgis eH
.mih llik ot deniamer hguone taht yaw on saw ereht tub
.ylsuovren denworf atsirab ehT
.dil eht devomer I
”?god a s’taht erus uoy erA“
”,gnos siht ot sdrow eht lla wonk I“
.ti gnivol rof rehtom ym detneser I dna
.gnikcilc saw gnihtyna fi esnes ot gniyrt ,seirots dlo gnillet
,delwoh dna ,dekaorc ,dewac
”?sdneirf llits er’ew oS“
.kcor cissalc ylno
.thgis ni erehwon saw rehtaf yM
.elteeb a ekil kool mih edam taht sessalg dnuor ,egral dna
”?yeht t’nod ,tuo rehto hcae pleh sdneirf“
.sseldneirf dna sselboj egelloc morf emoh denruter d’I
”.llac ot esle ohw wonk t’ndid I tuB .evird gnol a fo dnik s’ti wonk I ,yrroS“
.dias atsirab eht
”?mih deef uoy nac
.yawa deklaw I sa
”.yako s’taht kniht I god delppirc a rof s’ti fi ,yakO“
.ssarg eht ni nwod dehcuorc I
,yletarepsed ,dias eh
.htaerb peed a koot I
t’noD“ .edis eht no maerc deppihw fo puc ynit a dna
,osrot ym ta ylknalb derats god ehT
.onicippup a evresed ot ylgu oot saw eh thguoht yeht esac ni ,mih ees yllautca ot enoyna tnaw t’ndid I
.hcrep sih ot denruter dah nevar/worc eht taht dnuof dna
,ti gnilahni yllacitcarp ,decnuop eh
,dnuorg eht no maerc deppihw fo puc elttil eht decalp I os ,mih ot esolc oot sdnah ym tup ot diarfa saw I .ylteiuq gnissih
.og meht gnihctaw ,dehgis I
.detneirosid demees eh tub
.kaeb sti dekcilc worc tnaig ehT
.melborp s’esle ydobyreve ti ekam dna pu kaerb ot dediced dah gnitad erew ohw sdneirf owt ,noitaudarg erofeb htnom a tuoba tub
”,weiver eht tuoba tegrof
,god taht detah I
.krow dluohs taht kniht I“
.yrros“ ,dias eh ”,haeY“
gnitalitnevrepyh saw atsirab ehT ”.taht ekil skool
?gnihtyna naht erom nerdlihc rieht evol ot desoppus srehtom t’nerA ?em tuoba tahW
god/dad ym tuoba gniht tseipeerc ehT
,ytrid syawla saw ti taht noisserpmi eht evag hcihw ,etihw hsiwolley saw ruf siH
.etoyoc a sa nrober si ohw
”.rehtie uoy etah yllaer t’nod I“
,puc regral siht ot mih del I
”.sgniht emos dias ew wonk I ,oS“
”,sesirprus etah I“ ”.esirprus a s’tI
,gniward ni derojam d’I ,esroW
”?erew uoy taerg woh tuoba klat ,weiver rats evif a uoy evig nac I
.erofeb enohp eht no deklat reven d’ew ,egelloc ni esolc os neeb d’ew hguoht nevE
”.t’nod I fi derif teg ll’I“
.ylsuonimo ,kaeb sti gnikcilc tpek tI
.flesmih revo lla gniloord dna em ta gnippans
”.tey si ti tahw em dlot neve t’nevah uoY
”.em eveileb ot esimorp ot evah uoy tuB
,ralloc sih sdrawot derutseg eH
.raews I ,em ta dekool tI
.efil ym fo tser eht rof god elttil elbirroh siht htiw kcuts eb d’I
deredro d’I ahcom eht htiw denruter
”dliW eb ot nroB“
.yzarc sdnuos tI“ ”.eruS“
,cisum lacissalc dekil reven rehtaf yM
.egap muideM sih no seirots trohs erom dnif nac uoY
.cisum lacissalc devol eh taht
.dias I gnihtyna raeh ot mees t’ndid eh dna
.krap ybraen a ot rehtaf ym koot I
.trid eht otni depees ti dna
”?nwot fo edis ruoy no sworc yna ereht erA“ ”?yakO“
,ti gnillips ,ahcom eht revo delbmuts eH
,llams saw krap ehT
,nac hsart gniwolfrevo na fo pot no ti decnalab dna pu ti dekcip neht
yb uoy rof daer ,emaN ruoY yb
.ton ro ti dekil I rehtehw ,ssentiw a sa worc eht htiw ti od ot dah I os ,emoh ta rehtaf ym llik t’ndluoc I dna ,dnuora krap ylno eht saw ti tuB
”,god ruoy ees ot deen I“
”.pleh emos deen I .taerG“
”,eno doog a s’ti ,em tsurT“  .denihw eh
”eltiT yrotS“ saw sihT
,mom ym tuohtiw saw eh revenehw tuB
.sraeg eht hguorht ylhtooms detfihs I .thgir saw I dnA
,yrc ot ton gniyrt dna seenk ym gnigguh ,htrof dna kcab dekcor I
.eveels reh fo kcab eht no ecaf sih morf loord eht gnipiw dna ruf ygnirts
.dnuorg eht no ahcom eht decalp I ,txeN
”,taerg s’ti kniht I ,oN“
”.ta gnitteg er’uoy tahw wonk I kniht I“ .delims I
.puc onicippup elttil eht htiw gnola
hgih os saw ti litnu
?taht uoy esimorp I dluow yhW“
.edistuo og reve ot desufer ehs tub
.brubus ruo ni sesuoh eht fo sfoor eht evoba gnikeep tsuj ylno nus eht
.deneppah gnihtemoS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.kcurt dlo ’stnerap ym fo taes s’revird eht ni deppoh dna
,elbatrofmocnu tlef I ,saw ti drib fo dnik revetahW .ecnereffid eht llet ot elba neeb reven ev’I ,nevar a saw ti ebyaM
”.ti fo erac gnikat pleh emos deen I .driew gnihtemoS
.yug elttil eht ehtoos ot mees did ti ,timda ot evah I
,rehtaf s’eno nosiop ot dexim eb dluoc snoitulos dlohesuoh nommoc tahw dehcraeser I ,thgin ta etaL
.wohemos nwo sih no ti did eh ebyam ro ,denrut mih dah ehs ebyam rO
”.od uoy wonk I“ .dias eh
.god a evah uoy fi maerc deppihw fo spuc elttil tuo evig yehT
.kcab mih egnahc neve thgim ti
,puorg tink-thgit a fo trap neeb d’I
.em revo dessap wodahs krad A
.selgna lla ta tuo kcuts hteet sih dna ,ecaf dehsiuqs a
,toof ym rednu puc ahcom eht dehsurc I
.worC .rM ,uoy knahT“
,gnas eW .dennirg I
.taews ot gnitrats dna
.llems fo dnik htrae eht rednu ,nettor ,peed A
,mih gnitagorretni deirt d’I
,gnihtemos ro ,nrobwen ym saw epuolatnac a gnidneterp
.revetahw tub ,toidi na ekil tlef I
”.sdneirf llits er’ew ,haeY“
.taht ekil eman sih ees ot egnarts demees tI
.tsrif ta desufnoc saw I
.deliaf dah nalp ylno yM
gniralb oidar eht
,setadpu gnitirw roF
.dekeirhs reven tsomla eh
,dnuos a ekam t’ndid rehtaf ym emit elohw ehT
.sgnirtstraeh dlo eht no gnillup yrt ot tsuj
,yrgnuh skool rehtaf ruoY“ ”.rehtaf ruoy“
?thgir ,god ydal dlo na tuo pleh ot uoy tnaw dluow ssob ruoY
rettiwt no mih wollof
eht eb dluow sihT
.emoc t’ndid rehtom ym ,esruoc fO
”,yddub elttil yeH“
,edis eno no erutcurts yalp a htiw nwal dnuor a tsuj
.hsael eht htiw ti drawot mih deggard neht
.edisni mih fo tfel gnihton saw ereht