.gnihtaerb reh dehctih namreboD gnuoy ehT
hcihw ,keehc ym ot nwod yaw eht lla daeherof ym morf racs a htiw em tfel ti woN
si yrots s’yadot dna
,revewoh ,noitasrevnoc ruo fo eritne eht tuoba kniht dluoc I erofeB
,ydal ,taht htiw kcul dooG
elbuod a od em edam tsomla taht eno ehT
.detatiseh redienhcS .srM
”?si nos ruoy erehw wonk uoy oD :noitseuq tsal ym rewsna t’ndid uoY .haey ,hU“
?neht snoitseuq emos uoy gniksa trats I nac oS“
tnempiuqe ym no ssot
.sseug I ,oga sraey lareves ymrA eht morf degrahcsid tog I ecniS“
.gnikeirhs deunitnoc ehs
.rehtegot stsirw yrruf sih gniffuc nageb I
.hcum uoy rehtob t’now I dna ,etunim a eb ylno ll’tI“
.esle gnihtemos gnidih saw ehs wenk I
”,eman taht yas ton oD“
.esuoh xelpud eht fo edis tfel eht ot kcab gniklaw detrats dna denrut I
”.roverT elcnU ,gniht eruS“
.rethgual htiw gnippiy detrats ehs ,ylnedduS
”,yob ,egduj eht ot pu saw ti ,erofeB“
.dekrab eh ”!yrros m’I“
.renedrag detacided a ro efiwesuoh a evah I rehtiE
,ni yob eht gnirb ot em dewolla dna rehtom laciretsyh eht deldnah
”!uoy eus I erofeb og mih tel gnikcuf retteb uoy os
”!gnimoc m’I ,gnimoc m’I“
.nworf ytsan a otni gninrut yletaidemmi elims reh
”,uoy llet ll’I dna teiuq eB“
?00:11 ebyaM ?doog dnuos 00:01 seoD
,koobeton reh ni nwod gnitirw llits ,taes kcab eht ni yecatS dna ,kcab sih dniheb deffuc llits stsirw s’lyraD
.rood eht denepo I ecno nus thgirb eht ta gnicniw ,ylthgil dehgual I
gnilffuhs rehtruF
”...llits tub ,asac elgnis a naht asac a fo flah ekil erom ,lleW
”,tnegA .yrevoceR .liaB“
***   .ssilb suoicsnocnu ot kcab em dellup peels
,sehtolc lautca fo riap a no tup neht d’I
.yawa teef wef a nehctik eht otni gniklaw elihw wap a devaw I
,retal setuniM   ”.tnemmoc on
,sicoV sumoD yb
.ecalp siht otni detpecca gnieb yecatS tuoba klat enoyreve raeh netfo d’I
,ylno em dna meht gnieb ti no detnuoc I ,flesym yb ni evitiguf liab a gnirb did I snoisacco wef eht nO
--     ”.yppah eb annog ton s’eh ,haeY“
.nirg lausnes reh deniater yldrawkwa ehs ”?haeY“
.swap rieht no emit ralucirrucartxe hcum oot dah ylsuoivbo dray tnorf rieht detaroced reveohw ,enO
.’skcihc rof drazah gnikohc‘ a saw taht ’egakcap egral‘ a tuoba gninraw
asac iM“ ,deunitnoc I ,kcab seitnuob wef a thguob I eno wen a ,rotaregirfer eht otni gnihcaeR
dehgis I ”,yag ton m’I .oN“
”?worromot revo emoc…wonk
eseht ,sremotsuc gnikcuF“
.tuo mra na gnihcterts ,denway I
.ruf krad ym rednu elbisiv
.esnefed ni hteet ym derab dna reh ta sreggad der-toh deralg I
.sesac truoc ssim ot nwonk evitiguf liab a dneherppa ot gniyrt
.seiromem eht ta lwarc ruf ym tlef yldrawni I
.guht a m’I gnikniht otni flow-ehs eht koops ot saw dedeen I gniht tsal ehT
,roiretni yssem ym ta rednaw seye reh deciton I
.epat tcud emos dna nug nuts ym debbarg I sa pu doots yecatS
.ylevitcudes elkna ym ta dehsiws liat reH
.aciremA ni metsys liab eht tuoba s’ti ,thgin tsal uoy dlot I“   ".em
.ti devorp saw gnihtyreve naelc woh dna srewolf eht ta kool enO
.ni mih thguorb I sa doog kool ot ecnahc eht em evag ti woh gniees ,dnim t’ndid I
”?sevitiguf liab gnisahC“
,ffo tlob dluoc eh erofeb mih no pu gnikaens devlovni nalp yM
,srevotfel emos fo kcab eht ta sados owt gnidnif yllaniF
,flesym detaeper I ”,ma’aM“
dah ew tub ,rehto hcae rof tuo dekool mih dna eM
.krow ta ylekil tsom saw rehtaf eht woh gniees
kcurt ym tsniaga flow eht dleh I ,locotorp evitiguf derutpac reP
.namreboD elamef eht ni ecnedifnoc ykrans eht derimda I tub
.kcab pets ot uoy deen annog m’I“
:em htiw yrgna eb t’nod esaelp dna ,verT elcnU ekam ot noissefnoc a evah I“
”!yawa yob legna ym ekat t’nod tsuj esaelp ,tnaw uoy gnihtyna od ll’I“
.noon dnuora retal nageb yllaer yad eht litnu raewrednu dna trihs-t a tub gnihton
,egelloc otni og ot detnaw rehtorb elttil yM
”,srevognah staeb ti ,haey dna...ecatS ,egaugnaL“
,su tfel rehtom ruO
.retal gnimuucav tuoba thguoht dna ,sehsid ytrid eht dehsaw
,dehsinif I ”,si tniop ehT“
,thgiltops a ekil ni enohs
.dnatsrednu I .ecatS ,yrrow t’noD“   .ylitraeh dehgual dna eciwt deknilb I
”...enal tuokcehc dedworc eht ni ,ereht gnileenk
.ecein gniynapmocca ym htiw degnahc ti tub
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,deen uoy pleh eht teG
.nep dna koobeton a otno dleh ehs sa
.deremmats rehtom eht ”,lleW-W“
.derekcins yecatS
,yllaniF   ”!gniksa ton m’I
.ma’am ,niaga daor eht no neeb s’eh wonk ot ekil dluow ecilop eht kniht I“   ”—tuB“
.ecnelis tnew rac ehT
,drah dekarb ylneddus motA eht sa dehcnilf I
”?racs siht eeS .lyraD ,yeH“
”!siht ekil ton ,em ot gnineppah eb t’nac sihT“
.ytrap rebmuls a gnirud esuoh rieht otni kcuns eh nehw gnineppah warts tsal eht htiw
,redienhcS lyraD“
.wohs ytilaer diputs emos fo esuaceb ,tnega yrevocer liab—
.yadot rof stnemetats ssentiw ruo evig dna ni teg retteb eW“
.lavirra s’yecatS rof pu denehserf dna
.derumrum ehs ”...verT elcnU ,si retnuh ytnuob
”!timmad ,lanimirc a ton s’eH“
”,ereh kcab yats ot uoy tnaw I ,woN“
.sllib eht rof diap ylerab boj esohw cilohocla na saw daD dna
.revo si efil ym woN“
.sthguoht ym ni reh ot dias I
”?gnihtemos ro ytic eht gnieelf eb I t’ndluow ,evitiguf liab a erew I fI“
”.lanimirc a mih ekam stca esohT
,dik egelloc diputs a erew I fi tub ,supmac eht no ecnediser sih ta gnikool eb lliw enoyrevE
.kcab eht morf denaom yecatS
.od ot drah taht t’nsi ti tuo snruT“
.taeskcab eht morf ni denael yecatS
.em rof ksa dluoc uoy tahw wonk t’nod I ,lleW“ .deddon ehS
.syek eht reh dednah neht
”,sllac ytuD“   ”?ti si tahw ,huH“
”!sthgir gnikcuf evah I !og emmeL“
nwod sgniht gnitirw deppots yecatS nevE
”?em rof taht od uoy naC
.eye ym gnola walc sih sehctarcs gnikcuf eh
.retnuh ytnuob a erew I fi deksa ylduol dna em otni depmub reograb neknurd a nehw degnahc ti tub
,yecatS“ ,detuohs dna smra s’flow eht deppirg I ,pu mih gnillup tslihW
.flesym ot thguoht I ,worromot gnixaler rof hcum os
.tegrat ym fo doohrobhgien eht dnA
”?verT ,ereh eb eh dluow yhW“
?ecalp tsrif eht ni em wodahs ot deen eht leef uoy did yhw ,sdnob liab gnidnefed er’uoy fI“ ,deksa I
.egelloc doog a rof erudne ot dedeen ehs sessalc hguot eht dnA
,flow a saw eh ,eruS
.nwotnwod sdrawot sbrubus eht tfel ew emit eht yb niaga gniklat yllanif mih htiw suoituac tahwemos em edam
”!t’nac tsuj I .ris ,liaj ot og t’nac I
,noertaP ro trAtnaiveD no noitcif raluger dna yrruf etirw ot sevol ohw
.retsiger eht morf yenom gnilaets deirt dna
.boj ddo gniod elihw reihsac traM-dlaW a gnieb saw dnif dluoc I tseb ehT
.yecatS ,uoy ees ot doog s’ti...os
,eye thgir ym nwod gninnur eno tcaxe eht ot detniop I
.ecnelis rehtruf dna
”.ereh ylenol neeb ev’I“
”!verT elcnU ,thgin dooG .hcus dna scihte
.taorht ym deraelc I
.hgU .kool citehtapmys evag ehs
.gnilaeppa erom reh ekam dluow elgna hcihw tuo erugif ot gniyrt saw ehs ekil ,em dnuora ria eht ot em morf derednaw seye reH
.oot dluohs uoy dna ,oddik ,peels emos teg attog I“
H“   .liameciov ot og dluoc ti erofeb gniht nmad eht barg dna hgis ot ylno
,erahs ot dah su fo eerht lla tnemtrapa moordeb-owt ynit siht saw emoh ruO
”!lyraD uoy ees ot dooG“
?redienhcS .srM“ .ecneliS
”!lanimirc a ton s’eh tuB“
.yldeticxe dekrab yecatS ”!uoy knaht ,uoy knaht ,hO“
,tsap sraey morf em wenk ohw ssergit a ,sreciffo gniynapmocca eht fo enO
”!ydob ym uoy evig ll’I dna og mih teL“
ytnuob emit-lluf a emoceb t’ndid I“
tsuj m’I .ytinummoc TBGL eht sdrawot tsugsid fo mrof yna evah ro cibohpomoh ma I yas ot toN
.rediw rood eht gninepo erofeb dekoj I
.ecein ym ediseb gnittis elihw desiar seye ,deksa I
,rufdaeh deyd reh dehctam taht esuolb der a dna snaej mined nrot fo riap a gniraeW
,kcurt eht tsniaga yltfos derumrum eh
.yawevird eht fo tuo gnillor motA derekcits eht ees ot dnuora delrihw I   ”!hctib a fo noS“
,omem eht ot gnidroccA
.no delbmar I sa nwod sgniht gnitirw nageb yecatS   ”.wal eht morf nur eht no seog ro lairt sih dnetta t’nseod rehtie tub ,liab a rof syap eh nehw evitiguf a erutpac ot si boj yM“
”?oddik ,tnemom a em evig uoy nac
”,roverT elcnU ,sknahT“
ti tub ,dnuober doog a eb dluow ardneK thguoht I dna…dna
.gnirewol ylitliug srae reh ,desuap yecatS
”?dad ruoy dna uoy was tsal I taht ,samtsirhC ecnis ,neeb ti s’tahW
.yaw eht yb ,mih tuoba yrroS“
.kcab eno evig dluoc eh erofeb edisni dellup saw eh tub ,don truc a mih dereffo I
***   .ni gnisolc emac sneris ecilop
.lanimirc decneirepxe emos ton s’eh tub ,haeY“
.ylluferac detats I
.tnemssarrabme ni llef srae ym
,rorret fo noisserpxe gnirekcilf s’lyraD derongi dna
,kcurt ym detixe I sa reh dlot I
.yawevird eht kcolb ot drawrof dehcrul ylneddus kcurt ym ,euc no thgiR
,noitasrevnoc eht degnahc ylkciuq I
gniraew ,rewohs a gnikat ,moorhtab eht ot gniog ,emit revetahw ta pu gnikaw dnuora devlover gninrom fo epyt tsrif ehT
”!siht no tuo ssim tonnac I os ,taem hserf s’eH
,sredienhcS eht yb denwo erew srac eseht ,omem eht ot gnidroccA
”.em tuoba thguoht gnidaelsim taht evah dluow uoy yhw dnatsrednu I ,revewoH
,aera eht ni rab nwonk a ta tuoekats a no flesym dnuof I ,emit enO
”,nos ruoy rof gnihcraes tnega yrevocer liab a m’I dna yelniF roverT si eman ym ,netsiL“
delworg I ”!tsiser t’nod ,yddub ,tsiser t’noD“
.doom ym no gnidneped ,sgniht owt fo detsisnoc sgninrom lausu yM
,net ni tuo tog I
.kcab tup yldalg I hcihw ,modnoc desunu na dna yenom emos ,tellaw sih tpecxe gnihtoN
.noitats ecilop eht edistuo revo dellup yllanif I ,gnihgiS
”?rebmemer ,yadrutaS s’worromoT“ .ylitraeh delkcuhc ehs ”,epoN“
.drac tiderc sih gnilaets fo em sesucca dna ni semoc reveirter detanoinipo siht ylneddus nehw ruoh hsur fo elddim eht ni m’I ,yad enO
.stekcop sih gnihcraes detrats dna
”!ti rof +A na teg ot erus eb ll’I
.derepmihw dna nwod daeh sih gnuh neht
.rood edis s’regnessap eht tuo gnieelf deirt eh sa delbmurg I neht ,detuohs I
euqisyhp niht reH
a tahw s’taht tuB“
”.kcurt eht htiw ,hguoht doog did uoY“ .dennirg dna
.ekil eht dna delley
.ylniatrecnu yawa dekool flow eht ”,wonk t’nod I“
2 gninroM rof noitidart ym detnemelpmi I
”.ssalc ot noitatneserp ym rof ,boj...hu ruoy tuoba sgniht wef a wonk ot deen ll’I
.pu ekops eciov eninimef a ”?uoy era ohW“
,thguof ,emit eht lla dekrow amdnarg dna apdnarG
”!srekcuF !won ,og mih teL“
revo nur ot etatiseh t’ndid I tub
.em desirprus tsomla rood ym ta namreboD regnuoy ehT
”.ffo gniliart fo dnik era uoY“
dias yecatS ”,gniht eruS“
.tekcop thgir ym ni gnitarbiv detrats ylneddus enohp ym ,euc no fi sA
”,spirt esoht gnikat detrats dnabsuh ym dna ,egelloc ot ffo tnew eh ecnis revE
,hteet sih gnirab nageb lyraD   ”!ti od gnikcuF“
derekcins yecatS
.taerht a fo hcum t’nsaw eh ecnis
”…ma yllaer I .ris ,yrros m’I“
”—pu wohs t’ndid nos ruoy yhw wonk ot
.efil ruoy devas netfo aionarap
”?thgir ,ecitsuJ lanimirC PA rof s’ti dias uoY“
.ssakcaJ gnieelF-liaB ed asaC
.em dniheb gnikool saw redienhcS .srM woh deciton I nehw flesym tuhs neht tub
.moordeb eht otni gnillorts nageb dna tekcop ym otni kcab enohp ym devohs I
,yltnerappA .retal sraey thgie degrahcsid tog I erofeb tsaE elddiM eht ni sruot lareves did dna
”.siht tuoba yddad ruoy llet t’nod ,esaelp dnA“ .denaorg I
.emit revo delaeh eye eht ylikcul tub
.srekcits repmub dna oerets naem a htiw
.nur eht no erew eh fi og dluow
.delggig eciov ehT
”elcnU retnuH ytnuoB“
”.ti rof nur a ekam ot dediced dik bmud eht tub ,barg elpmis a eb d’ti thguoht I
.rood desolc eht hguorht gnitarbiv eciov gnirevaw reh
,ylirgna dednopser eh
.noitazilaer til ni em rof dehsinif yecatS ”,stneraP“   ”—eb dluow tahT
.koobeton reh ni gnitirw deunitnoc ehs sa
.skcolb lareves rof dehcterts taht secnediser rehto eht fo yna ekil dekool hcihw ,ytreporp eht deyevrus I sa
,tsugsid yratnemom gnihsalf
.evisneffo saw dias uoy gnihtyreve thguoht ohw sessa-thgit detatirri
”,dias taht ecno yduts a daer...I“
,elzzum reh koohs namreboD elamef eht
”...erus ,eruS“ .detneler I ,peels fo sruoh wef a nettog ylno gnivaH   ”?esaelP
,dehsinif dna denaorg I
,yob doog a si lyraD“
.elbuort ni teg I nehw og me‘ fo lla ecalp eno eht ot og d’I
”.oddik ,em htiw emoc ,pleW“
.tnapucco sti tuo llup dna
”!aliov dna romra ydob emos yub ,esnecil reporp a teg tsuJ
.tsev foorp-tellub ym no gnittup desuap I
.noitanitsed ruo sdrawot evord I sa
.gninrom siht gniraeh truoc deriuqer sih ot pu wohs t’ndid eh neht tub ,dnob liab 000,02$ a no tuo mih tog stnerap ehT
.’moor gnivil‘ s’reliart eht ot gninruter ,desolc egdirf eht dekcik dna tuo meht dellup I
,hcihw fo gnikaeps dnA“
.ytnuoc siht ni repmuj liab tnecer a tuoba txet a tog tsuJ“
”,sremotsuc eht erew dnats ton dluoc I tahw tub ,emit-lluf rof hcus dna llew diap ,tneced saw krow ehT
.efil ot kcab muh enigne rac a draeh I nehw s’tahT
.stnerap gnilddoc sih yb deliops
,boj ruoy yojne uoy syas daD“
”!lanimirc a ton s’eh tub ,si eh erehw wonk t’nod I“
”?yako ,nroh taht knoh ay
,ylduorp gnikrims ”,yltcaxE“
.eergasid yllanosrep ot neppah I tub ,’etairporppani‘ debbud gnieb rof sdnuorg si ti ,reidlos elamef wollef a htiw snoitaler lausnesnoc evah uoy nehw
,yltrohs dehgual I
ralgrub a dedneherppa ydaerla d’yeht ,sulP
.dnatsthgin eht no gnizzub enohp ym fo dnuos eht deretsiger ylerab niarb ym ,thgindim dnuora pu gnikaW   sicoV sumoD yb
.gnirekcins elbidua reh edih ot gniyrt t’nsaw yecatS dedneterp dna
.srae dedlof reh htiw yawrood ym dekcolb dna derepmihw ehS
.esaec t’ndid erats napdaed yM
?llems eht dna ,slaem ruo rof doof tsaf tae sulp
”.won taht od t’nod ,timmaD“
.metsys liab eht no si cipot ym dna ,ecitsuJ lanimirC PA rof repap siht no gnikrow m’I
.hcni erauqs cillatem yreve derettil taht seno edurc ,yseehC
ay…dluoc I fi gnirednow saw I tub ,uoy rehtob ot yrroS“
,hateehc eht fo srae eht thguac dah toidi ehT
.edistuo delbmarcs redienhcS .srM ”!yenoh ,lyraD“
’nwap etaroproc‘ a em dellac neht tub
"...ereh kcab evird annog saw eh dias...dias dna yadretsey ereh saw eH
,retal sdnoces wef a pu gnuh ehS   ”.thgiN“
,ruf revlis gniyarg htiw flow-ehs gnihtemos-ytrof a laever ot denepo rood eht ,niaga kconk ot tuoba m’I sA
.kcehcyap txen ym teg ot ssa gniluah em ot del yllautneve
”.lyraD rof doog gnikool t’nsi siht ,segrahc gniklats eht fo pot nO
”!og nos ym tel retteb sdratsab uoY“
”—eht goD dnes d’yeht wonk t’ndid I tub ,ereht dna ereh deps I timda ll’I
.relur latem a sa thgiarts m’I
”?’tnega yrevocer
.riaper dnoyeb ton tub ,yltnerruc uoy rof degamad s’tI
,tuo tog I emit eht yB
.od ot tahw wonk t’ndid I…tsuj I“
.gnineve eht ni retal VT hctaw dna
.delrans eh ”!?kcuf eht tahW“
***   .flesmih em redrum gnikcuf dluow rehtorb ym ,esiwrehtO
,deliart ehs ”,yllautcA“
.demrofni eb ot dedeen stnerap reh
.seye neerg reh erew tuo doots yllaer tahw
.wodniw reh tuo gnirats ,derednop yecatS
.regnif a detniop I
”...syad eseht sdik tneitapmi uoy ,lleh gnikcuF“
:yawevird eht ni sgniht gnitseretni wef a deton I ,revewoH
”.eniacoc no s’ti ekil leef niarb eht sekam ados egareva na ni ragus fo tnuoma eht taht“
.teprac s’pu-kcip eht ta erats ot elzzum sih derewol eH ”.derifkcab
.yawevird eht ni dekrap gnihtemos-ytnewt a yb denwo srac suoivbo owt eb ot deneppah ereht—
,lyraD gnuoy eht ot degnoleb ylraelc htob tub
,degrahcsid gnieb retfA
”?oddik ,ti si tahW“
”!stnemetats ssentiw evig ot su deen ll’yeht dias yehT“
hcihw ,aera eht ni ytnuob a sevlesmeht denrae evitiguf liab a nehw detrats yllausu
.dehgual ehs ”,tihslluB“
”!rekaeps no meht tog ydaerlA“
,snoitcennoc sah dnabsuh yM“
,esnopser etairporppa na saw noitacovorp sa hcum sA“
,em derehtob ylerab reliart ym edistuo dna edisni ria gnirps looc ehT
,shtnom wef a fo doirep a revo skcihc owt gniklats erew uoy em sllet elif ruoY“
a ro sedahs fo riap a htiw resol gnitot-nug emos ton m’I“
,ni deklaw ehs sA
,seye s’rehtorb ym erew yehT
.snaej dna retaebefiw dehcaelb a naht rehto gnihtemos raew neve ebyaM
.ylimaf ruo fo edis yelniF eht morf emac taht snrettap ruf nworb-dna-kcalb reh erew sa
.nac ym fo pis yvaeh rehtona koot neht
.emoh nekorb a ni pu werg ew tub ,ti tuoba sklat ylerar miJ
,hgU   .gniht nmad eht gnilgnatnu setunim wef a gnidneps em ot del deb ni mraw gnipeek rof ecnereferp ym tub
”?haeY“   ”?verT elcnU“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.retteb em wenk yecatS tub ,ffo ydal dlo ytsan a deracs ev’dluoc nworf yM   ”?tahw oD-D“
”.lla ta esac ruoy pleh t’now yawevird ’stnerap ruoy ni tnuts elttil ruoy dna
,desuap I nehw pis rehtona ekat ot tuoba saw I   .desuma ylraelc
”.gniht tseb txen eht rof tnew I os ,stset gnikcuf rieht deliaf I esuaceb poc a eb t’nac I tub
;eb d’ti thguoht I naht sselecirp erom saw ecaf s’yob eht no kool ehT
”!snoitseuq ym fo tser eht rewsna ot uoy deen I tuB“
flesmih lyraD dna stnerap eht—
.esolc dleh koobeton reh
”.yadot elbuort fo tol a ni er’uoy
.gnivigsknahT no reh morf yot a elots rehtorb redlo reh nehw erow eibod elamef eht ecaf deneddas emas eht dnA
”?he ,ycerces rof hcum os ,nmaD“
tarb ylurnu na htiw gnilaed eb annog m’I .daeh ym ni desimrus I ,taerG
,nep reh denoitisop ylidaer yecatS ”,woN
srebmem eerht gnivah ylno ylimaf s’flow eht etipsed ,owT
.gnihtemos rof uoy sdeen ecein ruoy woN
:oddik ,era ew ereH“ .xelpud a ediseb nwod su dewols I ”!hA“
.eciov ykahs a hguorht yas ot deirt eh
,emit eht dekcehc dna seye ym denepo I
,mmM“ .redlohpuc tseraen eht ni nwod ti tes ylluferac dna flesym ot delbmurg
sliame ynam oot eno meht gnidnes
”elcnU retnuH ytnuoB“ saw sihT
”.oddik ,’tnega yrevocer liab‘ si mret ehT“
.kcurt ym ot edistuo em wollof ot denrut ehs erofeb elims regae reh otni yawa detlem ylsuolucarim ecaf das s’yecatS
deunitnoc yecatS
.deripxe snoitpo htob ,yawevird levarg eht otni llup rac a draeh I sa ,yldaS
,ronim a saw ehs ecniS
.eninac tneitapmi eht ta delrans I
,erif etihw ekil truh niap eht ,oga sraey ti tog I nehW
,gniunitnoc erofeb desuap namreboD regnuoy ehT
,huh…dna em ekohc ot gniyrt s’eh ,wonk I gniht txeN
.hsael nori na ekil thgit mih dleh I tub ,niaga yawa gnimriuqs deirt lyraD
,diK ?og annog uoy erehw ,ereh fo tuo teg uoy fi nevE
.eldniK nozamA no ,"yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT"
”!ereh kcab emoC !t’nod uoy ,oN“
”!uoy htiw gnimoc m’I ,yeH“
.ssarg deird eht tsniaga nwod-elzzum mih dleh smra ym tub ,em rednu gnimriuqs dna gnikrab saw eH
”.efil eganeet ym ot enod saw egamad eht tub
,elzzum reh no gniraeppa elims neddus eht no desab tub egavaelc reh rof noitanigami eht ot gnihtyna tfel ylerab trihs-t wolley ,mils reH
.detneler yllautneve I
,yratilim eht ni gnieb dekil I esuaceb ti did I
”,ma’am ,ytrap rebmuls s’lrig a saw ti syas troper ehT“
wodniw edisdeb ym tuo noom ehT
.elttob ados a fo giws rehtona gnikat erofeb
,reywal a sa boj doog a tog eh dna ,raey a rof emoh retsof ni yats ot dah ylno rehtorb yM“
.ffo em devaw ehs ”!yrrow t’noD“
,kaeps t’ndid flow desufnoc eht nehW
,flow elam a fo tnorf ni gnileenk nexiv a gnitciped rekcits evisneffo siht saw ekat-
,loots toof/elbat eeffoc eht no rehto eht gnittes dna snac ados eht fo eno gninepO
.tac eht niartser em depleh poc ytud-ffo na erofeb skcolb ytic ruof gninnur pu dedne I .tnorf eht tuo nar dna knird sih deppord ohw
”.yddub ,uoy rof emac I nosaer eht t’nera stekcit ehT“
.reciffo ecilop gnitiaw a ot revo retsgnuoy evissap eht dednah dna elcihev eht detixe I ,gnilimS
!kconk ,kconk ,kconK
delwocs I ”!epacse mih tel ot em gnitcartsid erew uoy tub ,uoy ot ecin gnieb deirt ev’I“
.noitatneserp ym rof ofni hcum os em evag uoy gniwodahs ,sediseb dnA“
,deilper yltnatculer I ,gnihgiS
.erom ecno denway I
daor eht no desucof llits seye ym ,pu ekops I
”.lanimirc a tsuj m’I woN...daed s’tI
.drawkwa ylbidercni tnew sgniht erehw saw siht woN
...“   ”.taht naht lanoisseforp erom si boj yM .kcap tekcor
.repsihw a yb dewollof ,edis rehto eht no gnilffuhs emos raeh
”!esimorp I ,yaw eht ni teg ton dna taeskcab eht ni yats tsuj ll’I !verT elcnU ,esaelP“
”,retnuh ytnuob a sa...“
”,setunim wef a ni revo gnimoc s’rac ecilop a dias yeht ,haeY“
”.em eus ot nosaer laer a uoy evig ll’I dna ,yob ,ecein ym ta gnirats peek :yaw eht yb dnA“
,evitiguf detnaw a gnitteba dna gnidiA“
”!si sa elbuort hguone ni er’uoy ,ma’aM“
,ecnayonna ni delworg I
”,yecatS…hu ereht yeh ,hO“   ”.yecatS s’tI“
”.ecatS ,’tnega yrevocer liab‘ a m’I dias I“   ”?huH“
”...ssalc ni dekcip t’nsaw taht cipot ylno eht s’ti tub ,boj ruoy tsniaga m’I yas ot toN
.em ta worbeye nwo reh esiar ot denrut eninac regnuoy ehT
”.egnirc elbiB eht ekam d’taht yaw a ni em llik d’eh ,tuo dnuof reve daD ruoy fI“
.dluoc I sa reliart ym fo hcum sa pu naelc ot dediced ylgnigdurgeb I os
,od ot sgniht retteb gnivah spoc eht ot sknaht dnA
retsloh ym ni resat eht deppirg ylevitcnitsni wap tfel yM
.renaem ro ruos erom neeb evah t’ndluoc nworf yM ”.ton yletulosbA“
,reh dekil I reh dlot I ecnis em gnirongi tpek atraM“
”.verT elcnU ,boj ruoy od og uoY“
.flesmih ro meht ,em ta rehtie
,roirp shtnom wef a slrig loohcs hgih regnuoy emos gniklats eciwt thguac saw yob eht
”...worromot uoy ees ,hgu…tsuJ
,daor eht no deniamer seye ym
.lyraD ,erutuf eht ni tnaw uoy tahw od dna
.detaler erew ew devorp tI
.doohrobhgien roop a ni pu werg I dna rehtorb elttil ym ,ega ruoy flah saw I nehW“ ,denialpxe I
,em detpurretni redienhcS .srM
.afos ybraen a no nwod tas ylwols ehs
.gel eht ni tellub a ro racs rehtona tog I erehw syad citamard esoht fo eno eb t’ndluow yadot ,yllufepoH
,eye gnideelb ym dehctulc I sa smra sih htob ekorb I oS
,slrig tuoba snoitseuq drawkwa s’wehpen ym ro
”…hgU“   .niaga lanruoj reh ni gnitirw detrats ehS
”!?thgirla ,dnim thgir ym ni t’nsaw I-I“   ”.peerc a ekiL
”—t goD yb deripsni erew uoy taht dna
!oddik ,od eruS“   ”?mih tog uoY“
.ecnis reve em nevigrof reven s’eh tub
.eulb fo edahs a ni krap reliart ytsud eht fo tser eht gnitniap tbuod on
?gninrom worromot ecalp ruoy yb pots dluoc I fi gnirednow saw I ,yawynA“
,teirraH morf emac ylsuoivbo erutats trohs dna
”?ecilop eht llac dna rovaf a em od uoy nac woN
.peelsa-flah llits
.yratilim eht otni tnew I tub
,hguone elbatneserp dekool ti litnu ruf trohs ym hsurb ,deb fo tuo pmuj d’I
.flow-ehs eht ta seye ym denediw I
”,lanimirc a ton s’eh
.gnihtyna yrt mih ees ot ecnalg yllanoisacco d’I tub
”.evitcetorp yrev s’eH
,reh detcerroc tsomla I
.toof no esahc yna no og ot deraperp saw I ,yllamroN
”.ecatS ,trohs siht tuc ot evah ll’ew kniht I tub ,yrros m’I“
siht sa hcus elytsefil a gnivaH
,yltnecer esnecil sih gnisol dna snoitaloiv gnideeps evisnepxe wef a morf edisA
.enim morf pis llams a koot I
.stonk ni delgnat teknalb eht dnif ot ylno ,sserttam ym otni kcab gnispalloc erofeb dewollof I dna
esnecil dekover a htiw evird nos ruoy gnittel ylgniwonk sulp
.skrow eht dna sporp remmus ykcat ,dray yssarg A
”?ecein ym ot on dias I fi nameltneg a eb I dluoW“   ”?ni emoc I naC“
,krans reh ta gnillor seye ym gnirongi elihw
.semit eerht rood eht no dekconk yltnatiseh I ,hcrop tnorf eht ot pu gniklaW
?thgirla ,od ot tahw wonk t’ndid I dna ,dekcinap dna tnedicca yb ni tpels I“
.kcurt ym dehcaorppa ew sa
,enog gnol retniw htiw yllaicepse
...reh gnizisahpme ,tuo smra reh gnihcterts nageb redienhcS .srM
”!og s’tel ,neht no emoC !uoy knaht ,uoy knahT“   ”—dna taeskcab eht ni yatS“
dluoc I   ”?emoh uoy era ,redienhcS .srM ?olleH“
”.edud ,kcuf yloH“ ,derettum lyraD
?huh ,gnivird neeb s’eH“
.sthgildaeh gnihsalf ekil pu til seye ym ,stxet eht fo hcae gnidaer retfA
”?ereh gniod uoy era tahW“
”!yllis ,reeb ton dna ados knird uoy yhw ksa ot gniog saw I“
.tekcop kcab ym otni gnihcaer elihw
.nwod mih dleh I erofeb sdray nezod owt ti ekam neve t’ndid flow rebmit thgiewrevo ylthgils sihT ?lyraD dnA
,krow fo enil siht nI
.dik eht gnitcetorp eb ylbaborp ll’yehT
”.oddik ,krow suoregnad si sihT“
”elcnU retnuH ytnuoB“   :yojne esaelP
”:oddik ,noitseuq kciuQ“
.rac a tuohtiw enoyna edave ot hguone tsaf nur dluoc dna rehctans esrup-denrut-etelhta essorcal a saw hateehc ehT
.llub si esac elohw siht ,sediseB
.detcaer ylerab ,loohcs elddim ehs ecnis siht tuoba nwonk d’ehs woh gniees ,yecatS
”!verT ,klat ot eno er’uoY“
,redienhcS .L lyraD deman seitnewt ylrae sih ni flow ygdup a ,evitiguf liab detnaw eht detcepsus I
”...ereh emoclew syawla si ylimaf tub
”,enecs eht eelf ot gniyrt sthgir esoht tsol uoy ,yoB“
.efil ruoy htiw no evom dna liaj fo tuo teg thgim uoy ,yademos“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb
.gnihcaorppa deirt ehs
.tesolc a morf meht hctaw dna
,reywal a sa boj s’rehtorb ym ot sknahT
”—egrahc suoires a si lanimirc nwonk a gnidia esuaceb ,si lyraD erehw wonk uoy oD
.noisnet fo keew a derudne d’I ekil tlef I tub ,kcolc ’o eerht tsap flah ydaerla saw ti won yB
”?taht wonk uoy diD .yadot gniraeh truoc sih ot pu wohs t’ndid lyraD“
”?ma’am ,nos ruoy si erehW“
.sreh fo koobeton taht pu denepo dna deddon ehs
.niaga reve llec liaj a ni eb ot detnaw reven I
,nehctik eht ni dekcats sexob azzip dlo eht ,afos eht yb delip snac ados munimula deniard eht yawa dessot I ,drawretfA
,neethgie ta ymrA .S.U eht denioj dna detaudarg
.elims a htiw em ot denrut yletaidemmi neht
I“   .dehgual ylneddus yecatS
,yeh ,yeH“ .swap ym morf eerf flesmih gniknay deirt ylevissergga flow rebmit deffuc eht ,erom ecnO
.gnitadimitni...ssel raeppa ot gniyrt nehw pleh t’ndid ylniatrec
”.od ot retteb gnihtyna evah t’ndid I sseug I
,dnob ruoy gniyap no tuo deppiks uoy esuaceB
sgnilbmar tnassecni s’wal-ni-retsis ym gnirongi ,sgnirehtag ylimaf ta deregnil I revenehW
.elkcuhc desuma yldrawkwa s’yecatS ro
.nwot fo dne rehto eht no loohcs etavirp ycnamcs-ycnaf a otni rethguad sih teg ot deganam eh ,snoitcennoc emos sa llew sa
.namreboD a eb ot deneppah I tub
,noisseforp ruoy tuoba snoitseuq wef a ksa ot deen tsuj I
”?ris ,tniop
.siht rof llaf t’ndluow I
,rorrim weivraer ym morf dehctaw I sa ,dna
?yako ,enohp ruoy morf ecilop eht llac dna nwod kcud ,sneppah gnihtyna fi tub ,dab oot eb ll’siht kniht t’nod I“
.taes nugtohs eht ni mih htiw lleh sa esnet erew setunim evif tsrif ehT
,ylduorp seiddub tseb owt...reh
”?siht tog I woh wonk annaW“
.etunim lluf a rof racs eye ym ta gnirats fo lautir gninrom ym did I ,rewohs a gnikaT
”!ecatS ,ffo liat ruoy yrrow t’nod ,haN“   ”—gnihtyna ro emit dab a ta uoy gnirehtob ton m’I epoh I“
flesreh desopmoc ehs
.reh rof dezisahpme I
”.taht uoy ksa ot gnitnaw neeb ev’I
,mlap ym ni neercs ssalg eht otni derumrum I ”?...olleH-
.krow fo dleif siht ni seidal mret-gnol htiw ykcul tog reven dna renol a
!norom ,ffo ti kconK !yeh
?boj siht gniod neeb uoy evah gnol woh“
”.yrt ll’I .ris ,yrt ll’I“
.riahcmra s’afos eht no mra ym detser dna ados ym deppirg I
,heH“ .rewol ylneddus srae dekrep reh deciton I
”?tahw ro revo gnimoc hctapsid ecilop a si ,yecatS“
”!gnivah erew yeht ytrap a ot mih etivni ot ton llag eht evah yeht neht dna ,ecnahc a yob ym evig t’ndluow stuls esohT“
,gnikoob ot detrocse eb redienhcS lyraD dehctaw I sA
.ta si lyraD erehw wonk t’nod I“
.top elgnis a ni derrits yllufituaeb noisluver dna ewa detanicsaf fo erutxim a
,em edisgnola gnillorts nageb dna edis regnessap eht detixe ehs
motA dettiftuo na rehto eht dna ,dnarb noillatS citsur a saw enO
liab‘…a emoceb uoy did yhW dnA
”.ecatS ,gniht eruS“
.delevirhs yldrawni I
.kcab os ro raey a litnu tnemecrofne wal fo noitnetta eht niag t’ndid eh
levon tubed sih dnif nac uoy dna
.kcurt eht morf deilper ehs ”!ma I“ ”?yako uoy
.efil ni slaog…tnereffid
?esuoh a otni gnikaerb dna snoisacco etarapes no slrig owt gniklats htiw degrahc si nos ruoy wonk uoy od ,ma’aM“
.rac rieht ni moor hguone evah t’ndid dna
,ereh kcab em deen uoy fi dnA
”!t’nsaw rac eht tub ,teiuq gnieb deirt I !moM ,yrros os m’I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,verT elcnU ,taht naht erom eb ot sah ereht tub ,yrros m’I-
.kcehcyap ysae rehtona gnitteg em tnaem taht
”—od ,retnuh ytnuob a sa“
.drawnwod deyalps srae dna sgel sih neewteb dekcut liat
,nekatsim saw eh mih gnillet deirt I
taorht ym deraelc I
.noitisop sih etipsed kcen sih gninarc ,ria eht gnitib deirt flow ehT
”?uoy era ohw ,tiaw...eruS“
.thgin tsal saw mih morf draeh I emit tsal eht ,naem I“
,detsisni flow-ehs eht
.trihs ym fo tnorf eht no noitpircsni ’tnega liab‘ ym ot detniop I
”.yelniF roverT si sihT…sihT“
.ees dluoc eye eht sa raf sa sdray tnorf ni semong nedrag dna syot citsalP
.esneffo peed ni deffuh ehs ”,ereh t’nsi eH“
.wodniw ediskcab eht tuo daeh reh dekop yecatS
.pu-ekam hcum oot dna dliub muidem
,reh htiw noitats eht otni gniklaW
”...boj a no em htiw gnieb uoy tuoba thginot llac enohp taht steg eh nehw yas annog s’rehtaf ruoy tahw htiw denrecnoc erom m’I ,tnemom eht tA
,lla dna boj sih htiw tahw ,em fo dnof oot t’nia spop ruoy wonk I .asac us se
.dne rehto eht morf dellac eciov elamef railimaf ,suovren-flah a
.reeb no erahs riaf sih tneps daD ecnis ,rehtorb ym dna em troppus pleh ot boj a dnif ot loohcs fo tuo deppord I ,yawynA“
”—ot yaw a dnuof reven I tub ,ksa ot detnaw syawla ev’I gnihtemos s’erehT“
.nopaew a otni ti detcefrep dah ecein ym dna ,retal sraey neveS
”,depacse tsomla eh tluaf ruoy ton s’tI“
deen nemsdnob ehT ?ta si eh erehw wonk uoy oD“ .ytnuob 000,05$ a tsol I ,siht rof llef I emit tsal ehT
.aibrubus dehctap-neerg fo ezam a gniretne dna krap reliart eht morf raf erew eW   .dekrims I
”?verT elcnU ,siht mih gnillet ot tniop a ereht sI“   ”—ti ,doG dooG
.loohcs morf dna ot meht gniwollof dna
”?loohcs rof deb ni eb uoy t’ndluohS-S ?oddik ,ruoh siht ta ’nillac uoy er’yhw ,hfM“
.shtnom evlewt rof eivuj ni yats ot em deredro llits egduj eht
”?thgir ,dekover saw esnecil siH
.sedud rehto otni t’nsi elcnu ruoy ,eveileb ot drah s’ti sa hcum sA“
.em ta ylsuoiruc decnalg dna
.srae trela ym ot enohp eht dleh dna deb ni pu tas ylisword I ,gninaorG
.em sdrawot teef evif deppets ,smra reh gnivaw dna citnarf won ,flow-ehs ehT .derelloh ehs
.stxet lareves dnif ot tuo ti dellup I ,edisa knird ym gnicalp retfA
eht s’tahW“ .ecneserp sih gnigdelwonkca ecein ym ta denethgirb-flah
gninrom fo dnik dnoces ehT
.ylderit delahxe I
”!gniht elgnis a egnahc t’now ti
semoh rieht fo eno otni kaerb ot dediced uoy nehT
.eelf nac yeht gnikniht ssabmud eht teg ot tuo og dna
,denworf-flah flow eht ”,eerga I“
”!em s’ti ,roverT elcnU yeH“
.sdnob liab tsniaga noitatneserp a gniod m’I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
nwotnwod raB sbulC ’o gniK eht yb seugaelloc emos htiw tuo gnah ebyam
,srotisiv tog ylerar I tnaem
,loohcs ot kcab tnew I ,oS
.nruter on fo tniop eht tsap er’uoy woN“
”!emitliaj rof sdnuorg si
”,hcum ytterP“