.setunim evif rof sknuks tuoba pay ruoy tuhs ll’uoy fI“
.srednow skrow yrettalF .dias I
.pohs eht ta uoy rof yad wolS“
em yarps dna dnuora nrut
.etalp ym no ruf fo dnarts etihw ro kcalb yarts a teg semitemos dluow I ,renid eht ta laem a deredro I nehW
.ojnab sih pu dekcip dna delworg trebuH
.serots rieht ro semoh rieht ni rehtegot rehtag meht ees I
.seceip kcalb ym fo eno devom I
.emit taht rotciv eht tuo emac I
.elbat a fo retnec eht ta seldnac fo lufdnah a til meht fo enO
.taorht ym deraelc I
ereh siht ni sdnuoh eht lla ot ti nwo I ,ydarG hairU fo yromem eht nI“
.ainigriV ,epirtsdaorB revo nekat dah sknukS     bmobknukS yb
”!ti ot pots a gnittup m’I ,lleW
ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.gniknird tuo gniog m’I“
.’sumarongi na er’uoy syas amaM‘ ro ’thgin ta
”.detivni ton er’uoY
.detnahc dna elcric a ni derehtag yeht nehT
”.yrt erom eno ,on ,tiaW“
.toof reh morf yah dlo fo tib a dehsurb
,revo tneb sknuks nezod a naht ssel on dah I
.dekrab I ”!won no emoc ,hO“
.erutcip eht ta
.sgniteem knuks terces tuoba gnihtemos wonk yam
seceip kcalb elttil roop ym derutpac eibO ,dezigetarts I ygetarts tahw rettam oN
.ylsuoigiler dehsaw ehs ro , taht
”.reeb a uoy yub ll’I ,ycaripsnoc knuks on s’ereht taht daeh kciht ruoy hguorht ti teg uoy fi ebyaM
,daeh a llac uoy nevo pu-degnid taht ni gnikooc aedi yzarc emos tog ev’uoy wonk I ,nreV“
.eson sih fo egdirb eht dehcnip eibO
.321bmobknukS sa
”.elbuort ni teg d’I ,em dlot aP dna aM terces a uoy llet I fi dna
”!dekan er’uoy nehw but eht ni pu dnats t’noD“
.em ta gnimia lla ,nwod dellup stnap ro pu dekih sesserd
?pu og liat sih tel t’ndluow eh fi
”,elbat tluda eht rof hguone dlo tsomla er’uoy ,lleW ?11“
,dedne gnitnahc eht nehW
.saw gniteem terces sih erehw em llet ot mih teg d’I ,gni-gnik dna gnipmuj trepxe ym htiw knuks eht delzzad I elihW
”!sknuks ffo gnissip dnuora og t’nod uoy taht s’nossel ehT“
”?xob eht ni kcab seceip eht tup em pleh tsael ta uoy nac dnA
.mih dniheb demmals rood neercs ehT
”?eciuj otamot no dneps ew yenom eht htiw egelloc ot og ot erodoehT rof yap dluoc ylimaf eriM ehT“
mraf a ,mraf ylimaf eriM eht taht emirc a ton ti sI
,dehs ym pu xif ot dedeen I slian eht no laed doog a em evag eh dna ,llabtoof tuoba klat ew dna ,semitemos sdrac deyalp I dna eibO
.noitaterpretni ot nepo s’tahT“
”?nossel ruoy denrael yllanif uoy ,oS“ .dias trebuH
.rood llats eht fo edis rehto eht no erew ohw em llet ot seye ym deen t’ndid I
”.nreV ,enola yob eht evaeL“
.ecnartne taht gnihctaw saw eno on tub ,seno tnorf eht sa ediw sa tsuj nepo erew srood kcab ehT
ereh sihT“ .elbat nehctik eht no ti denepo I
”—evitisnes mugdad os t’nerew yeht fi ,lleW“
.xaw eht yawa dekcilf dna rae ym ni regnif ym delggiw I
seenk ym htiw noitpircsed suoreneg a eb thgim taht—tperc I
.nreV ,ekas tsirhC roF“ .mih
.seye sih gnirevoc ,dias trebuH ”!nonreV ,timmaD“ ”!nwot
.tros emos fo ynomerec noitaitini na ylsuoivbo saw tI
.serugif euqseutats rieht rof nwonk t’nera sknuks ,woN
.xocliW lehtE saw taht erus saw I
”.sknuks dnuora gnipoons luferac erom eb ot deen ll’I tahT“
”?siht ekil yad a no od ot sgniht retteb tog uoy t’niA“
”,taht llems nac nwot elohw eht kniht I“
ydarG hairU fo eman eht yb god dnuoh gnidnatspu na yb dednuof saw nwot
”?srekcehc fo emag a htiw pu ekam ew tuoba woH .yrros m’I ,kooL
remitroM haidabO yas dluoc uoY
draob eht pu tes ew dna
dias knuks rehtona
.ssenkrad eht ta detniuqs I
.deggurhs knuks ehT
,nwot siht ot gniod era sknuks eht tahw no sweiv emas ym dloh ton yam eH
.daeh sih dehctarcs
.mih pmuj ot noitisop otni eceip ym devom I ”!oot ma I“
”.thginot em gniees eb t’now uoY .dneirf depirts ym ,yrrow uoy t’nod ,hO“
.sessalg sih gnitsujda ,dias eibO
”.thginot gnorw sknuks esoht enod I ,trebuH“
.nwot fo tuo yaw ym no delkcuhc I
”.nreV ,draob eht gnihctaw ton er’uoY“ .delkcuhc eibO
—galf gninraw ruoy s’ereht ,ees uoy U.P—
.denialpmoc pih dna seenk ym fi neve ,pu detlob I
”.erodoehT ,gninrom doog ,lleW“
mih revo lla nettirw swen dab
.epip bocnroc a no depmohc dna deredluohs-daorb saw em dniheb knuks ehT
”?sesuohtuo gnidliub no koob a evah uoy od yhW“
.eciuj otamot fo snac dna seotamot fo setarc htiw dekcots nogaw der a gnillup saw—
.yllems dna ytriD .ytrid
yenom ruo revo dnah ew nehw
”knukS ekiL sllemS
llihrednU luaP deman efilwol emos ,royam rof nar eh erofeB
.gnitaehc tnatalb hcus nees ton dah I ,efil ym fo sraey 36 eht lla nI ”!em
.gnivil llits elihw lleH ot teg nac dnuoh a tsesolc eht s’tI
”.kool a evah ,no oG“
”.sknuks esoht gnirehtob og uoy erofeb erots lareneg eht ta eciuj otamot emos pu kcip ,esac taht nI“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,bmobknukS yb
”,daerb emos yub ot ni yaw ym no tsuj saw I“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
ym dewang dna srae ym ta deknay I
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
,nonreV elcnU dnarG“ .kool a koot trebuH
”.ris ,gninrom dooG“
”!eibO ,noonretfA“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tibbangad dna ,nwot eht delur sknukS
”?eb taht dluow erehw ,tros emos fo gniteem terces a ,wonk t’nod I ,rof stnerap ruoy gninioj erew uoy fi ,woN“ .y a ni sdne taht yad yreve em no skrow tI .em tsurT
dniw eht ot eson ym detfil I
.deppots knuks ehT
# .daerb yub ot togrof I derebmemer I erofeb emoh yawflah saw I
.edur os lla erew yeht tub ,semoh rieht gnitisiv deirt I ,tsap eht nI
.drawretfa shtnom rof em no knits eht llems d’I
.erots lareneg eht edisni deirrucs dna nogaw sih debbarg erodoehT ”.ris ,seY“
.ruf ym fo tuo kcip ot kcen eht ni niap a eb ot gniog saw eciuj deird ehT
”.ereht eb ll’I ,haeY“ .dehgis eibO
,htaerb ym dleh I
”,gib ytterp gnitteg er’uoy ,yM“
ainigriV ,epirtsdaorB“
”.ris ,aedi doog a s’taht kniht t’nod I
ainigriV ,epirtsdaorB“:yojne esaelP
,sknuks fo gniteem terces a tuoba wonk dluow enoyna fI
,seitrap ,sgniteem nwot rof ti desu dna pu ti dehctans nwot eht os ,ti desu reven ti tliub reveohW .nrab dlo na
”.sdrac der lla fo dnah a tog ev’I dna
.sih fo ssenlufhsab taht ,citcat yranoisrevid revelc a saw tI
”,seicaripsnoc bmud ruoy tuoba lwoh uoy hguone dab s’tI“
.tnedicca etelpmoc a saw
.erimda dluow lived eht ylno ssensselhtur eht htiw
liat yM ”.dlihc a s’erodoehT tub“ ,erots sih drawot kcab gnidaeh ,dias eibO
esuaceb ,kcab eht morf nrab eht dehcaorppa I
,seye owt yrev ym htiw ssentiw ot tuoba saw I sa ,dna
.raW liviC eht retfa
,snoitacilbuP laoG rof dnaH a flesruoY eviG ygolohtna eht detidE ohw
.eno rehto eht debbarg dna ti dekcuhc I
,snigeb emag rekop eht erofeb gnidlof ekil s’tahT“
,kcab dehcaer ehS
.eson ym delknirw I
.dnah sih htiw ti dehsurb dna
.mih htiw srobhgien knuks sih lla thguorb eh dna ,nwot eht nioj ot deksa
dah ehs ,hguoht lehtE
.knukS .deffins dna
”.etamkcehc si ,dneirf ym ,tahT“
”.ti diova nac I fi ton rehtaR“
,ylimaf eriM eht fo knuks tsegnuoy ehT
.seceip ym fo owt revo depmuj knuks ehT
.sraep ekil depahs er’yehT
elcric eht fo elddim eht ni knuks eht
.yzzit a ni sevlesruo tog htob ew ,won yeH“
?tnorf eht hguorht gniog yhtlaets eb nac ohw
.teef sih ta gnirats erofeb tnemom a rof eye ym teem ot ysetruoc eht dah ylno eH
,yrebbor a troper ot ffirehs eht llac ot detnaw I
,emit elohw eht eson ym dleh I
.evom t’ndid I fi em ees ton thgim knuks ehT
”.ris ,rehtie wonk t’ndluow I sseug I ,terces a erew ti fi ,eeG“
liat sih debbarg erodoehT
?terces rehtona tuoba balb dluoc I naem taht t’ndluow ,terces eno tuoba debbalb I wenk uoy fi tuB“
.erots eht drawot deklaw eh sa
”knukS ekiL sllemS
llems yllaer dluoc I os ni denael dna
.eciov sih ni elkcuhc elttil a
.deppalc seinnin depirts fo tol eht dna ,seldnac eht tuo welb
,dnuohdoolb elbon eht ,em otnu dewotseb dah doG
.gel ym fo edisni eht dehsurb
,terces a llits s’ti esuaceb ,uoy llet t’ndluoc I ,em dlot yeht fI“
.ti evorp ot gniog saw I
.txen og ot erehw kniht t’ndluoc tnenoppo ruoy os ti od ot yaw eht saw evisiced dna kciuQ
,elbuort hcum oot em gnivig t’nsaw pih yM
.seceip der sih fo eno devom dna deggurhs eibO
.stah detniop dah yeht tub
ot tuoba saw eh fi wonk ot desoppus I saw woH
.erots sih ot txen pmuts a no
—pmuj dluoc I neht dna ,dnim ni dah eh evom revetahw ekam saw od ot dah eibO llA
,noisavni knuks eht ot sknaht oS
.xob a gnihctulc sllats eht ot revo derednaw knuks detaitini ylwen ehT
”,daer enod ev’I tahw ees emoC“
.emoc t’nod esaelP
rehcir teg dna sgod dnuoh tsenoh fo tuo suzeejeb eht gniyarps dnuora og sknukS
deknud I ”.nossel eht t’nia taht tub ,ebyaM“
.nwot ni srettirc depirts-etihw esoht fo thgis hctac ot ton dnilb eb ot evah d’uoY
.dah srekcehc fo emag eht ycneced yna fo tfeht a
erodoehT ”.su ylno
si yrots s’yadot dna
gnignahc saw ehs elihw reh no ni gnikeep
.llits yltcefrep tpek I tub
.htuom gib ym revo sdnah ym palc dluoc I erofeb llats eht fo tuo detlob dna
.em llet nac uoy tuB“ .traeh ym dessorc I
.enac ym debbarg I
”?taht od uoy d’woH
.knuks dlo ytfarc a saw eh tub
.tollab eht no knuks a syawla s’ereht tub ,royam rof noitcele na niw god dnuoh a ees enod reven I
,321bmobknuks@ rettiwT no dnuof eb nac ohw ,bmobknukS yb
.daeh sih koohs trebuH
,pohs eht otni tnew knuks rehto eht retfA
.but eht otni rewol depmuls I
.nihc ym rednu dehsaw dna
!tiucsib a fo noS“
.knuks a rof ,seye eht no ysae saw lehtE
pleh emos deeN“ .deggaw liat yM
.llats eht fo tuo deklaw I
.esle gnihtemos saw ereht tub ,ereht esirprus oN
”?ffo looc ot klaw a ekat uoy tuoba woH“
demaercs lehtE ”?taht htiw
.sllats eht fo eno otni—
thgif dluow eh ,dnah reppu eht dah I emit ynA
.but eht otni kcab dehcuorc I
,lleW .nwot ni ymene tsetaerg ym saw droffeM
.sevlesruo knuksed nac ew os
,ees dluoc I sa raf sa dna ,resol eht rof saw seceip eht pu gnikciP
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
ria yrtnuoc fo ffihw peed a ekat dluow I
,em no skcirt gniyalp t’nsaw gnithgil eht fI
.nwot otni klaw a fo ytuaeb a saw tI # ”.daerb fo
.knits rieht llems dna
.yteicos rieht otni detcudni eb ot ereh saw I taht eil saw od ot dah I llA
.ni gnimoc yarg eht htiw neve ,lluf dna tfos dekool llits ruf reH
.erodoehT yb tlenk eibO
deruop dna ,but eht ni tog ,draykcab eht ni sehtolc ym deirub I # .derif sknuks ehT ”—ces a tsuj tiaw won yeH“
?raeh uoy ,sthgin wef a rof dehs eht ni peelS
?enola sknuks su evael ot gniog uoy era nehW
”?ylrae gnisolc fo gniknihT
,llew ,saw nrab nwot dlo ehT
.deloof t’nsaw I tub ,sessalg fo tes a dniheb em ta deralg eH
”?taht si nossel fo dnik tahW“ .daeh ym dehctarcs I
but eht ni hsurb gnibburcs dlo eht
tseb ym gniod saw I tub
”.seceip der ym fo eno s’tahT“
,srekcehc fo xob eht dna sloots owt tuo thguorb eibO
,flesym no eciuj otamot fo nac rehtona gniruop retfA
?toidi na ,I saw tahW
.dekcilf liat s’knuks ehT
,sknuks eht fo gniteem txen siht tuoba tuo dnif ot gniog saw I fI
.hguoht nwot ni syawla erew sknukS
.repins a fo mia eht dah knuks ehT
.pissog rof tuo rae dna peek dna
dna sredivid llats eht fo sgnur eht fo eno otno pu gel reh detfil ehS .smag
.drawrof eceip kcalb rehtona deppils I
,raew dluow yteicos terces a denigami I sebor fo tros yna gniraew t’nerew yehT
ot epoH“
rehtiE .ega dlo fo gniwolley eht htiw deniats t’nerew sepirts reH
,em ot txen llats eht deretne knuks eht nehw feiler fo hgis a tuo tel I
,nrab eht fo trap krad eht ni nevE
.ti ta decnalg trebuH
”.od uoy sa hcum sa tsuj ereh gnoleb ew ,timmad tub ,sgod t’nia er’eW
,ees uoy ,rodo ehT—erodoehT
.gniyas erew yeht drow a tuo ekam t’ndluoc I
ot yllaitrap dna flesym gnillems morf peek ot yrt ot yllaitrap
.kciht t’nerew sllats eht neewteb srab eht
?raeh uoy ,yawa yats uoy ,nreV“
detniuqs I ”.regdab a s’ereht taht dna ,etihw dna kcalb ni s’koob eht
.nwot fo strikstuo eht dehcaorppa I sa selohrae ym ta dekcirp lio emos fo deen ni sleehw nogaW .seotamoT
.enac ym gnigniws ,yawa deklaw dna pu tog I
,eveileb ot eb yam ti sa drah sA
”?ees ot elpoeP ?eb ot secalP“ .deksa I
taht lehtE ot denialpxe tsuj dluoc I fi enif eb dluow gnihtyrevE
”,draob eht ta gnikool naht gnihca ylleb dna gnittahc emit erom tneps uoY“
.erofeb thgin eht deddeb dah eh nooccar emos fo gnillems
”.gninialpmoc ton m’I“
,gninrom hcae pu ekow I nehW
.hcrop eht no yawa teef 05 doog a ojnab sih ta dekculp ,eson sih no depmalc nipsehtolc a ,trebuH .eson ym ni gnignits eht tuo kcolb
03:01 s’tI‘ ro ’?ereh gniod uoy era tahW‘ ,lla saw tI
”.sgawyllacs etihw dna kcalb meht tub gnihton s’tI .erutcip siht ta kooL
nevele tsap emitemos rood eht ni deklaw ,wehpen-dnarg ym ,trebuH
.hturt eht gnidulcni ,gnihtyna tuo ffins dluoc taht eson a
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.ruoh siht ta mih morf eciuj otamot yub em tel eibO gniht dooG“
.tuo siht gninnalp eb ot evah yehT
mih gnirul ,dias I
.ydob ym nwod dna ecaf ym revo eciuj otamot dloc eht
reffins dlo ym wollof saw od ot dah I llA
”knukS ekiL sllemS
.delwoh dna eson ym no dnah ym depmalc I .deffins I
.egdelwonk ym nwod ssap ot
.yks eht ni sduolc ekil-peehs erew ereht dna
”.ydaerla em llet dna hsub eht dnuora em gninnur potS“
.mrots eht erofeb mlac eht saw tI
.yletilop uoy gniksa m’I tub
.erofeb knuks a yb deyarps neeb ev’I
.eson ym gnilknirw dna pu gnikcab ,dias I ”,ereh evil t’nac sknuks uoy naem t’ndid I ,won yeh ,lleW“
.sserd reh dniheb reppiz eht rof gniporg
.nwot eht eman ot thgir eht now dna royam rof noitcele eht ni ydarG taeb llihrednU
.llems knuks eht fo esuaceb ton dna
ainigriV ,epirtsdaorB“ saw sihT
?nwot ni eciuj otamot dna seotamot fo reilppus tseggib eht saw ,sknuks yb denwo
.erots eht fo tnorf eht drawot gniklaw ,dias I
”.ris ,11“ ”?51 ?41 ?won uoy era dlo woH“
.moor gnivil eht ni riahc eht no deppolp dna ojnab sih pu dekcip trebuH
”?ti t’nia ,yadrutaS a fo ytuaeB“
.draob eht fo edis s’eibO no nwod ti deppals dna seceip ym fo eno debbarg I
,dias trebuH ”?won ehs seoD“
.thgir saw reknits dlo ehT
.pu koob eht gnidloh ,dias I
?noitnevretni eniviD ?tfarchctiW ?dnah fo thgielS“ .pil
.ylimaf eriM eht eb dluow ti
.reyalp srekcehc noipmahc a saw I
eus os ,deppils regnif yM“ .deffuh I
”?yako ,kcolc’o 7 .thginot nrab nwot dlo eht ta uoy ees
”?eibO ,ti saw hcihW
.ega ym flah enoemos ekil gniggaw saw I  ”.setunim
.rood llats eht fo pag eht rednu keep dluoc I ,dnuorg eht no talf dial I fI
.knuks ekil llems syawla dluow ainigriV ,epirtsdaorB ni ria eht ,ton ro ti detnaw I rehtehW
.nogaw sih dna knuks eht dnuora dna pu deltsuh I
.sgnirehtag knuks terces
.nrab taht ni sknuks nezod-owt neeb evah tsum erehT
”?yadot nwo ruoy no seotamot esoht kcots uoy dluoC“
”?smag ecin tog s’lehtE“
.snaeb ekil sterces sih llips dluoc eh os ytiruces fo esnes a otni
”.uoy dlot enod yeht yas s’tel tuB“
dna su neewteb terces a eb d’ti nehT
.ecreif gnihtemos gniggaw saw liat yM
.erew sknuks eht erehw og ot dah I
,em fo tnorf ni deppets eibO
tuo er’eW .syawyna erots eht ot gnidaeh eb lliw I tuB“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
eibO tub ,tauqs wonk t’nod sdiK