seye sih llor namrehS edam taht ”stsohg niart fo foorp tsrif eht gnitteg“ tuoba esnesnon emoS
.wolg egnaro mraw rieht
.syadawon gniht gib a s’tahT
tsuj s’teL .erofeb ecnedive etercnoc yna nettog reven ev’eW“
redrocer epat eht no pitgniw a tup namrehS
”!hcum yrev uoy knaht ,ereh revo gniyats eb ll’I
namrehS ta eugnot eulb sih tuo kcuts eH
.mih ot tuo gnilleY
:ecnaveler elbissop fo oslA
.liat nwo sih gnildduc
evilC fo edis eht ot tuo sgniw sih devom ylikahs namrehS
,segdirb ,sdaorssorc no nees sgniht eht
.secaf rieht derevoc taht sksam erow lla yeht sa llab edareuqsam a dednetta evah tsum yehT
.nees eb regnol on dluoc eh litnu
”?tey driew gnihtyna deciton uoy evaH“
,ti dniheb dekcud dna
.ecaf s’dneirf sih otni pu dekool evilC dna
.sksam eht rednu ecaf a fo kcal eht saw ,hguoht semutsoc rieht tuoba trap tsegnarts ehT
.won yb gnihtemos deirt evah dluow yeht ,stirips suoicilam erew yeht fI
.enil eht ni sbac erew ereht naht niart eht ot noitcennoc lamronarap elbissop a tuoba sromur erom erew erehT
sgel sih fo dloh a teg ot deganam eH
dna retfa yltrohs hguorht dehsup daeh eht fo tser ehT
.os kniht uoy dalg m’I“
.oot ti deciton dah evilC
?uoy rof hguone driew t’nsi sniart dlo no sedir thgindim gnikat em llet ot naem uoY“
.pitgniw sih fo hcuot eht ot htooms saw ecafrus elohw ehT
sllaw rac niart eht ffo dednuoser taht keirhs gnicreip-rae na tuo tel eH
.tnih eht ekat ot syob eht rof gnitiaw ,mlap reh tuo dleh ehS
sgniw sih tuo dehcterts eh
gorf a fo epahs deniltuo na tuo ekam dluoc yeht
.evitomocol eht sdrawot srac eht fo lla
.gge na dial dah eh hguoht sa
.nwo rieht no sevlesmeht tneiroer ot syob owt eht gnivael ,rood enigne eht hguorht
.gnitsefinam saw taht tirips wen eht decaf dna
.epahs otni kcab gnicselaoc erofeb ,skraps egnaro otni gnisuffid
.srehtaef sih tuo deffulf dna ylwols pu doots eH
!gnitcaerrevo er’uoY“
emac reven taht tcapmi na rof flesmih decarb evilC dna nwod evod erutaerc ehT
.erom ecno talf srehtaef sih yal ot kaeb sih desu dna
”.tnereffid eb dluow emit siht gnipoh tsuj saw I .haey ,haeY“
namrehS fo srehtaefliat eht nwod revihs a tnes dah gnikaorc ehT
.retlehs sih dniheb morf delbraw namrehS ”?stsohg gnicnad fo edarap sseldaeh eht naem uoy oD“
.htuom sih otni spihc eht fo eno deppop eh sa deggurhs evilC ”?won thgir yrgnuh eb uoy nac woH“  .”spihC tekcirC“
.semit elpuoc a rac niart eht dnuora dekool ydaerla s’eH
thgil egnaro fo sllab erew meht dnuora llA
yrots s’yadoT
”.nmuloc a ti llac dna ecneirepxe ruo hsillebme
liat sih depparwnu evilC
.ecalp tsrif eht ni noitnetta sih teg ot gniyrt eb t’ndluohs eW“ ,derepsihw eH
”.ssim ot drah yrev s’tI !taht ees did I haeY“
og tel erew namrehS dna evilC ,rac eht ni ecnO
ni pu til saw rac niart eritne eht litnU
dneirf sih edausrep ot tseb sih did namrehS
.ssem elohw siht ot gnitcaerrevo saw eh ebyaM
.trihs sih fo cirbaf eht dehcnip dna hcni na fo noitcarf a htuom sti denepo ylluferac erutaerc eht erofeb
.htuom sih otni kcab eugnot sih gnillup retfa dias evilC
knuhcak-knuhcak-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hC  ”.eganam ll’uoy kniht I wohemoS“
.yaw taht pu wohs ot stsohg eht rof tiaw dna staes eht no tis ot dediced dna gnidnats fo derit werg htob yehT
sbir eht ni evilC degdun eh nehT
.meht gniflugne thgil reggib eht yb
.meht otni kcehc ot noitagilbo na dah yeht ,bulc noitagitsevni lamronarap s'loohcs rieht fo srebmem sa dnA
tuo deffuns erew srecnad eht sa soahc saw tI
ydob evissam sti desahp ti sa knarhs erutaerc ehT
.gnorw saw sregnessap rehto on erew ereht nehw rac regnessap eht ni gnieb taht
mih rof gnitiaw saw enoyna fi ees t’ndluoc eH
,edis-ot-edis daeh sih koohs tirips ehT
.desolc erew seye s’evilC taht was dna mih morf ssorca taes eht rednu dekeep namrehS
.ssendas dna feiler fo
.yldeticxe deksa evilC
niart siht ffo em teG !hguone s’tahT“
rac niart eht fo edis eht rof thgiarts dedaeh saw
ygolohtnA laminA naecO orhtnA nA :keeW krahS
?ti no raet dna raew elbisiv on evah dlo taht niart a dluow yhW
”.reh fo yteritne eht dloh ot hguone gib eb dluow taht tcurtsnoc a saw ti esuaceb tliub gnieb saw niart eht sa
.elpoep fo puorg wen a yb deyojne eb nac ffuts dlo erus gnikaM
.yob niart siht no stirips on s’erehT“
.tsrif rood eht hguorht dekop tuons nailitper a
loohcs eht ta pu gnihtemos kcip ot evah dluow eh nehw tog eh gnileef emas eht saw tI
”.su ees nac eno siht kniht I ,namrehS“
,adlihnurB niart eht gnillac detrats sklof os ,tsom rof lufhtuom a saw tahT
,skoob daeR-oT fo draoh sih morf gnidaer ton s’eh nehW
”?namrehS ,kniht uoy od tahW
!tsohg ssendoog ot tsenoh na s’tahT !namrehS“
?meht fo epuort gnicnad eritne na enola teL
”.yltneg os pu uoy nekow evah t’ndluow I esle ro liat ruoy dnuora gnipeels etuc dekool uoy ykcul er’uoY“
.redrocer epat eht mih gnireffo nevE
.ees ton dluoc ti gnihtemos rof gnikool eson s’ti
.ti revo deretsalp elims tseggib eht dah
.ssap ot ti teg dna yrt ot derevihs dna
,klof elbon fo seniltuo eht dah stirips ehT
.psag a elfits ot dah evilC
.tsael ta s’0081 eht morF ?thgir niart dlo na eb ot desoppus si siht ,taht tsuj s’tI“
thginot ”adlihnurB“ ni
.ria fo ffup a htiw eson sih ot kcuts taht rehtaef a yawa gniwolb ,ffo ti dehgual evilC
”.taht nialpxe thgim taht ,hA“
.yawyna neppah annog si gnihtyna ekil mees t’nseod ti ,sediseB
”?namrehS naem uoy od tahW“ ”?skool niart siht doog woh driew s’ti kniht uoy od ,evilC“
”.gninrom eht ni reporp ffo deppord teg uoy erus ekam ll’I .yfmoc sevlesruoy ekaM
.wodniw eht hguorht dna
ydob lartceps s’adlihnurB ees lla dluoc yeht ,edisni gnikooL
.os did eh sa rehtegot spil sih gnikcams
,noitarbelec s’evilC ni erahs ot detnaw namrehS
.nibac eht otni tuo depees taht htmraw tnasaelp a ecneserp reH
,ydob sih hguorht dessap
.sgniw sih ot kcuts mug dlo fo eceip a
,skooB goD wobniaR yb
.namrehS dna mih ta nwod kool dna
roolf eht tih evilC ,rac niart eht hguorht desruoc thgil eht sA
gniciton rotcudnoc eht tuohtiw niart eht otno teg ot saw aedi ehT
.deretne taht thgil fo tniop eno tsuj t’nsaw ti ,emit siht dnA
.mih rof deksa dna pu ekops namrehS ,yllufknahT
seye sih nepo dluoc eh taht namrehS llet ot tuoba saw evilC
.wen dnarb tsomla dekool staes eht taht deciton namrehS
.dnuof eb ot sraet ro spir on tub
knuhcak-knuhcak-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hC  .noitommoc tnecer eht fo lla hguorht teiuq ylsuoicipsus neeb d’eH
,evilC ot gnihtemos repsihw ot tnew namrehS
.ffo teg ot spots niart eht litnu tiaw ot evah ll’ew ,lleW“ ”?tahw woN
.skcans emos dloh ot kcap ynnaf a htiw gnola daD sih morf deworrob eh redrocer epat a dah evilC dna
,dias dna noitanretsnoc ni kaeb sih dekcilc namrehS
.pu sdnah sih tup oot eh sa
.did yllaer eh ,evilC eveileb ot detnaw namrehS
,dias dna delims ylliT
srecnad eht taht was eh nehw flesmih deppots tub ,pu dnats ot og ot tnew eH
.siht otni mih deklat dah evilC taht eveileb t'ndluoc namrehS
,sklof rehto morf nettog dah yeht stroper eht morF .rac
.erofeb sa ylisae sa tsuj
,dias dna daeh sih koohs evilC
”.ylleb rieht ni knird toh a htiw meht llet I tahw tpecca ot gnilliw erom era klof dnif I“
.gniees erew yeht tahw eveileb t’ndluoc ohw
dednal htob yeht dna evilC otno kcab llef eH
.oot thginot tuo gnissim m’I wonk uoY .taht ekil eb t’noD .no emoc ,yeH“
,dias dna daeh reh koohs ylliT
.mih dnuora pu gniffup morf
”.retsud rehtaef yffulf yllaer siht yb detsud gnitteg saw I dna noisnam s’erianoillim a ni esav evisnepxe na saw I
.gniw s’dneirf sih no dnah sih tup eh sa
yawa gniwots erew yeht ,seitrap neewollaH ot
”?taht od dluow eh kniht uoY“
.evilC ot revo kcab ti dehsup ylwols dna
.ereh neve er’ew llet t’nac eH“
.niart eht no tsohg eno tsael ta s’erehT .evilC yrrow t’nod
.tuo kcab aremac ruoy teg ,kciuQ
.derewol erutsop daeh sti dna
.meht fo owt eht fo reiknal dna rellat eht saw namrehS ,siht fo esuaceB
.gnicnad erew yehT
.won rof yawa ecnatsid efas a tis ot detpo dah namrehS
eht fo edistuo serutcip emos ekat tsuj dluoc yeht taht evilC ecnivnoc ot deirt namrehS ,niart eht no tog yeht erofeB
semag sekam taht nogard a si ohw
,sredluohs sih deggurhs
.mrah on naem ew wohs ot yrt s’teL“ ”?od ew od tahW“
.mih drawot nwod daeh sti gnivom saw erutaerc eht taht deciton eh nehw
enigne eht otni luos reh derrefsnart ehS
.rac niart eht edisni kcab sgniw sih llup dluoc namrehS litnu dah eh lla htiw dellup dna
.rac niart eht fo ssenitpme eht dna
”,kooL .niaga rehtegot kcab emac yehT
.meht hguorht dessap uoy nehw naem I ,oN“
daeh sih denrut ylwols namrehS
.seye rieht ni daed meht fo owt eht ta erats ot nwod flesreh derewol ehs sa eciov reh otni tperc dah lworg A
daeh ruoy hguorht ti teg ot tog evah uoY“
reh wollof ot meht fo owt eht rof denoitom ehS
.aremac tnatsni eht htiw ,ylikahs ,mih fo serutcip emos koot neve namrehS
.gniw sih htiw yawa dnah reh dekcams eh tub
.gnilknirc gab a fo dnuos eht yb sthguoht sih fo tuo thguorb saw eH
.sgel retrohs dna
.htrof dna kcab dnah sih gnivom elihw evilC ot derepsihw namrehS
dna rehto hcae ot gnirepsihw erew owt eht elihw gnivom deppots dah thgink gorf ehT
.enigne eht fo trohs tsuj pots a ot delbmut yeht dna
.samajap depirts fo riap delevehsid a gniraew moor eht otni gnipmots emac raguoc gnikool delzzarf A
,kniks a saw evilC
.evil ot nogard a rof yaw on s’tahT .evom t’ndluoC
?derotser saw ti ebyaM“ ,htiw
a ekiL ?nogard a si adlihnurB taht em gnillet er’uoY .tiaw oS“
.gniw sih htiw tuons s’evilC gnippals ylthgil yb dednopser namrehS ”.erac od uoy ,wwA“
.taes eht rednu morf tuo flesmih dellup dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY ,syawla sA
.rac niart ereh siht evael ot si ,siht fo enoN“
tsap welf ti sa htuom s’erutaerc eht ni deirrac gnieb
.stirips eht sa egnaro tneculsnart
.gnivom deppots dah
.niaga syob owt eht
.eid ot gniog ylniatrec tsomla saw eh
”.em rof hcum oot lla si sihT
.gnivom llits erew yeht ,hguone eruS
,orf dna ot dedilg srecnad ehT
.rehtruf gnilarips morf mih deppots dah ti dalg saw eh tub
”!evilC gniht doog a eb ot desoppus ton s’tI“
knuhcak-knuhcak-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hC   .nwo sti fo mhtyhr a ni skcart eht gnola delttar ti sa maets pu gnikciP
.dootsrednu syob eht fo rehtien egaugnal a ni ylpeed dekaorc dna
,osrot yltsom saw evilC taht yas ot noitareggaxe na t’nsaw tI
.ria eht otni gnulf gnieb fo noitasnes eht saw tlef eh gniht txen eht dna
.aremac tnatsni sih revo denrut dna
.moor ytekcir eht ni swodahs eht fo tser eht denethgieh swodniw ssalg eht hguorht gninihs edistuo noom lluf eht morf gnimoc thgil ylno ehT
.wodniw eht tuo gnikool saw eh taht deciton dah meht fo htob won
?deracs gnikool em fo serutcip emos ekat ot tnaw uoY“
sgniw dna sgel sih tuo hcterts ot elba saw eh taht woN
trihs nwo sih debbarg eh
.mra sih rednu temleh sih deirrac dna romra fo tius thgil a gniraew saw eH
.maerd tsegnarts eht dah I .namrehS yeh ,hO“
.liat sih gnieb mih fo trap tseggib txen eht htiw
.dias dah ehs tahw wollof dluoc eh erus t’nsaw llits eh hguoht ,deddon dna redic eht deppis evilC
.tuo ekam t’ndluoc yeht taht egaugnal taht ni stsohg eht neewteb srepsihw denethgirf erew erehT
er’uoY ?evilC yzarc uoy erA“
”?tuoba yppah os uoy era tahW“
”?uoy htiw od annog I ma tahW“
”!lla retfa ni eracs doog a teg ot deganam eW
.aremac tnatsni eht mih evig ot namrehS ot denoitom eH .taes sih no nwod gab eht gnittes erofeb htuom sih otni ti deppop dna gab sih morf pihc rehtona koot eH .deddon dna pu tuons sih dekrep evilC ”.ffuts
.suomrone saw kcen s’ti ,saw ti revetahW
,pu ,pu mih gnillup
,meht evoba gnihtemos ta pu gnirats lla erew yehT
”.od I tahw s’tahT
.em htiw llew tis t’nseod tsuj tI“
.redic mraw fo puc a revo no gniog saw tahw denialpxe dah
.seye ruoy nepo t’noD“
rac niart eht nwod yaw eht lla daeh sti hcaer ot hguone gnol ylisaE
,deneppah s’taht gnihtyreve retfA“
.yltnangidni deprihc namrehS
.noitceted diova ot gnipoh
dah ti taht ees ot detanicsaf saw dna
.ton er’uoy desirprus m’I .thgin eht flah pu neeb ev’eW“
gnola gnidils epacsdnal eht ees dluoc eH
.weiv morf dehsinav thgil eht ,ylgnisirpruS
.rood enigne eht ot revoc eht kcab dellup dna
.ti htaeneb srecnad eht derettacs dna
,sgniw dehctertstuo s’namrehS ta deggut dna
,redluohs sih rednu morf tuo temleh sih devom tirips ehT
,denway dna seye sih denepo eH
,namrehS dehcaer dah thgil eht nehW
ecnedive cihpargotohP
”.sselmrah yletelpmoc er’yehT“
tsrubtuo sih detterger yletaidemmi evilC
.gnimrof nrettap a ees dluoc owt eht ,dnuora devom yeht sA
,tib a sevren sih fo emos elttes ot pleh did ereht evilC gnivaH
.redrocer epat sih no dekcilc ydaerla dah evilC tub
reh eltnamsid ot tnaw d’yeht
.ylkciuq ytisnetni ni werg ti tub
noitatneserp neewollaH laiceps a fo trap sa
.rac ytpme eht dnuora dekool dna taes eht rednu morf tuo kaeb sih dekop namrehS
,etal siht nar sniart eht kniht t'ndid eH
,niaga htaerb rieht nettog htob dah yeht nehW
.rood eht dniheb paeh a ni
ydob elohw reh tub ,ereht ni rellams hcum saw ehS
taht os enigne eht ot tsesolc tops eht dekcip dah evilC
,toohsotohp llams rieht dehsinif yeht sA
.enigne eht dnuora delioc
”?nogard ssendoog ot tsenoh ,laer
”.pu sdnah ruoy tup ylwols yreV
sa thgil egnaro ni dehtab saw rac niart eht fo elohw ehT
.snoihsuc eht no ega fo sngis yna yldrah erew ereht tub
.reilrae rac niart eht hguorht ssap fo edam si adlihnurB taht thgil egnaro emas eht was ew ,si yas ot snaem namrehS tahW“
”.raf os em rof dekrow s’tI“
ruo daer ohw elpoep eht htiw tih a eb ot smees syawla tahT
.yllamronba gnitca eno eht saw evilC ,namrehS oT
.rof derac evah dluow namrehS naht reipeerc laed doog a llits saw ti tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,nus eht ot erusopxe morf noitarolocsid emoS
knuhcak-knuhcak-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hC .nosirapmoc ni seotatop llams si esle gnihtyreve taht gniyfirret os gnihtemos nees sah
.yhs eb tsuj thgim stsohg eht taht
.taes eht rednu kcab dekcud namrehS dna
kcen trohs a tnaem hcihw
.redluohs s’evilC no gniw sih ecalp ot revo tnew dna
.gnitniop saw dneirf sih erehw revo dekool dna
,siht eciton t’ndid eh elihW
.oga seirutnec srac eht krow ot desu taht rotcudnoc dlo eht retfa
?su truh ot sediced eh fi tahW
,ylthgit emit siht
rorret latrom fo ecaf eht ni ronaemed mlac sih rof noitanalpxe eht taht desirprus tsuj saw eH
noicipsus gnisuora tuohtiw rac regnessap tseraen eht otno ti ekam ot deganam wohemos dah yehT
.pets ycnuob sih ni raelc msaisuhtne
.yawa gniklaw detrats dna
”.ma’am nettogrof ydaerla ti redisnoC“
yletaidemmi tuo ti tips eH
?emit tsrif eht rof tsohg a gniees ot tcaer ot desoppus eno saw esle woh tuB
nibac eht ni wolg ehT
liat sih delggiw eH
,gnidrocer saw ti erus ekam ot redrocer epat sih dekcehc elbuod evilC
ni derutaef neeb yltnecer s’eH
.dednah ytpme kcab ton semoc ,regnad htekees ohw eH
.rac niart a otni dna eltsac a fo tuo deppets dah yeht ekil dlrow eht lla rof gnikool
,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer
emas eht denrut
”.redic hcum oot elttil a dah evah thgim uoy kniht I
rac niart eht fo gniliec eht hguorht dehsarc
”.rac niart eht ni tirips rehtona s’ereht kniht I
,kaerb ot gniyrt saw eh eno saw tibah ehT
.kcap ynnaf sih morf redrocer epat sih tuo gniggid elihw dias evilC
elttil a demriuqs evilC
”,gnihtemos fo kniht ll’uoy erus m’I“
,retal sruoh ekil tlef tahW
,tuo denael dna elop ybraen a dnuora liat sih depparw evilC
,dias dna elttil a denworf ylliT
seirots neewollaH gnidaer er’ew keew siht dna
”?taht s’tahW ?namrehS ,hU“
tuo derettacs taht
,dias eh ,ekops txen eh nehW
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
.flesmih detcelloc eh sa mih dleh evilC
.ti tuoba kniht t’nod neht lleW“
.tros emos fo thgink a eb ot deraeppa taht
tsetorp ni smra sih devaw eH
knuhcak-knuhcak-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hC  .meht woleb deraor
.gniyrc yltfos saw dna
.ecnaveler elbissop fo ,brevorp dlO .lla ta fI
,ffo nworht tog yeht enoyreve llet dna noitats niart
.tuhs seye sih tpek dna dlot saw eh sa did namrehS
.gninrom litnu ti edir dna
,tirips eht drawot gniklaw ydaerla saw evilC tuB ”?uoy era gniht taht ot klat ot gniog ylsuoires ton
”.uoy htiw od ot tahw yltcaxe wonk I ,lleW ?huh ,syawawotS“
.devirra ti sa esnemmi saw
,gnituohs taes eht morf tuo detrad eH
,efas saw ti taht ecnahc a gnikaT
”.tey deppots t’nsah ti desirprus m’I ,ti fo kniht ot emoC
”.yldneirf er’eW ?eeS“
,meht rednu gnidih saw eh nehw eciton t’ndid eH
,ees ot thgis suoiruc a saw tI
.namrehS ot revo kcab aremac eht dednah evilC
.selacs sih mraw dluoc eh
feiler fo hgis a dehtaerb namrehS
,htiw dednopser dna ylduol oot elttil a taorht sih deraelc namrehS .rewsna ot noclaf eht rof detiaw dna
”.yltcaxE“ ”?tahw raeH“
.dedraob yeht retfa yltrohs ffo koot niart eht
,dias dna taes eht fo edis eht morf tuo kaeb sih dekop namrehS
.detagitsevninu og seirots eht gnittel htiw enif saw namrehS
,renetsil ,flesruoy rof ecnaveler taht egduj tuB
,rethgirb saw thgil eht taht woN
.fooh gnipleh a reffo t'ndid ,yrots ralucitrap siht revo lla eb dluow thguoht namrehS ohw ,lúaR nevE
”.rac niart ytsum a rof pu ytinutroppo taht ssap dluow ohw sreloohcs hgih fo tol a toN
wolloh dna thgil erew senob sih taht mih dednimer eciov rehtona neht tuB
.ylluferac nwod tas dna rehto hcae gnicaf staes esohc yehT
thgil egnaro fo llab suomrone nA
thgil egnaro eht taht
,wohemos tser s’rac eht no
thgil egnaro fo setom otni detapissid mrof sih ,revewoh
mih revo hsaw gnileef eht tel eH
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.noitpecxe na saw 2835
”.siht otni hcraeser fo tol a enod ev’I ,em tsurT
*duht* a htiw rac niart eht otno kcab dednal eh nehW
erutseg eht dnatsrednu ot demees erutaerc ehT
.tirips eht sa desufnoc sa dekool evilC
.teem nwonknu eht dna nwonk eht erehw secaps lanimil rehto eht lla dna ,snoitats niart
selacs rebma krad dna wolley elap fo llab a ni pu delruc saw eH
.ti od tuoba tsuj dluohs tahT“
.retal ecnerefer rof thguac teg dluow dnuos yldlrowrehto eht taht gnipoh tbuod on
”.yrutnec eht fo poocs eht teg d’ew emit siht gnipoh yllaer saw I
rood rac niart desolc eht hguorht dehsup saw ti revetahW
,tsrif ta tniaf saw thgil egnaro ehT
.taes s’tolip eht morf demaercs eciov gnilrans a ”!adlihnurB“
,rac niart eht dnuora ylwols deklaw eH
”.neppah taht tel t’nac I
.ytivitca lamronarap fo debtoh a eb ot desoppus saw niart eht
?enigne eht ni pu dne ehs did woh tuB“
srehtaef sih delliw eh sa
taes sih morf pu tog eH
.senihcam ynam ooT“
.em ro uoy sa evila sa tsuj si adlihnurB ,gninnur llits s’ehs sa gnoL
”?taht ees uoy diD“  .did evilC
”.peels yllanif ot hguone nwod mlac dluoc ehs os thginot tuo reh koot I
,rehtnap emit-lluf a
evilC ta kool ot dnoces a rof noitirappa eht ffo seye sih koot eH
,emit siht mrofer ot regnol meht koot tI
”.suoires eb t’nac uoY“
!topkcaj eht tih ev’eW“  .gnimaeb saw eh
dnuora denrut evilC
srecnad eht fo eno ,nar eh sA
eciton ot tub pleh t’ndluoc eh tub
rac niart eht ni degnahc dah gnihtemoS
.tfel dah srehcaet dna sdik eht lla retfa
,gniyas erofeb pal sih revo dial ti taht os liat sih detsujda dna delims evilC
.hguorht ees mih edam taht egnaro tneculsnart elap a saw tser ehT
.gnihtaerb neve s’evilC fo dnuos tfos eht raeh dluoc namrehS ,ni denael eh nehw tub ,reilrae tuo ti denword dah niart eht fo dnuos ehT
.eromyna gnivom niart eht raeh t’ndluoc yeht taht teiuq oS .teiuq yliree
sserpxE thgiN eht tub
.dednuos taht sa drusba sa
.ti gnivah t'nsaw eh tub
,yradnuob eht htiw edilloc dluoc eh erofeB
.thgilnoom eht ni dam ekil gnitnilg seye
,pu hctac did eh nehW
.noitarepsaxe ni sgniw sih pu worht dna
.ton ro feiler a saw taht fi erus t’nsaw eH
.gnorw ton er’uoy ,lleW“
,meht dnuof dah taht raguoc eht ,ylliT
”?tinni rednow a s’ti tuB
”?taht raeh uoy oD
.oot gnitrofmoc saw ti tub ,suodnemert saw edisni morf taeh ehT
,dettils dna staes eht sa gib sa erew seye ehT
.reh no ytip koot tnua taerg-taerg-taerg-taerg-taerg ym esuaceb ereht tog ehs ,si rettam eht fo tcaF
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.yrots a retfa gnisahc eb ot desoppus t’nerew yeht erehwemos otni dekaens d’yeht emit tsrif eht t’nsaw sihT
.rac niart eht morf yawa pu
.lla retfa yerp fo drib a saw eh tnaem noclaf a gnieB
.snolat dnih sih no gniwehc ylsuovren saw eh deciton eh litnu soiranecs esrow dna esrow htiw pu gnimoc tpek namrehS
”?namrehS gnizama taht t’nsI !gnizama s’tahT“
.emoh og ot tnaw tsuj I“
.evilC no kcehc dluohs eh taht dediced dna nwod nolat sih tup eH
”.ti htiw tcatnoc ekam dna yrt ot gniog m’I
.depoh eh tahw s’taht ,tsael tA
.niaga ecno rac niart eht gniretne saw
.tser s’thgin doog a teg ot maets emos ffo nur ot sdeen ehs dna sseltser steg adlihnurB semitemoS“  .gnipeels saw ehs hguoht sa dekool ti dna dnuorg eht gnola talf dial saw
”.reh ees ot ecnahc eht tog uoy dnA
.tirips eht morf noitcaer on llits dnA
.raef htiw dliw erew seye s’namrehS
niart eht fo gniknalc emosenol eht yb detceffa eb ot mees t’ndid evilC
knuhcak-knuhcak-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hC  :ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC   .goD fo tsohG eht no
.slavretni modnar ta dnuora gninrut
.niart eht fo tnemevom eht
srae rieht ni deltsihw dniw ehT
,ereht rednu seidob rieht teg ot ezeeuqs thgit a saw tI
?gnitcaer eh t’nsi yhW .ti teg t’nod I“
.noissim rieht rof thgil dekcap dah yehT
”?thgink gorf eht dna stsohg gnicnad esoht lla tuoba tahW .stirips eht nialpxe t’nseod taht tuB“
.drazil gib ay nom’C“  .nihc sih rednu elkcit ot srehtaef sih desu dna tuons sih ot revo dehcaer namrehS
.edis rehto eht no tsuj detsefinam dna
”?tsohg a emoceb ot gniyrt uoy erA ?gnikniht uoy erew tahW“ ,deksa evilC
”.sriah gnittilps tsuj er’ew tniop taht ta tuB
gnidurtni saw eh ,mih dnuora srehto tuohtiw tahT
.moc.irikenen.www no
.kcit reh sekam tahw tuo dnif dna
eb ot demees dnuos ylno eht dna
,thgin taht emit tsrif eht roF
,daeh sih no ti tup
”?gnimaerd saw ehs ,oS“
ylwols dnuora denrut namrehS
,namrehS morf kcab gum eht barg ot revo dehcaer ehS
”?enigne eht morf niart elohw eht srewop ehs dnA“
tuo delleps taht tnof tcapmi dlob ni ogol a dna edis eht no
”!ecnedive siht revo sdnim rieht esol ot gniog era bulc noitagitsevni lamronarap eht ta kcab syug ehT
niart eht ni neppah ot gnihtemos rof gnitiaw ruoh na tuoba rof doots dah
niart eht ffo su wollof ,esrow rO
.thginot ytrap neewollaH taht ot og ot tnaw t’ndid uoy rednow oN
”?tuoba s’taht tahw wonk uoy oD
.pu til seye reh neht dna
,mih htiw etacinummoc ot gniyrt saw erutaerc eht tahw ot sa delzzuP
evilC dna namrehS
dnoces a rof thguoht ylliT
enigne eht ot revo deklaw ehs sa
rac niart eht fo dne rehto eht ta sdik dennuts eht ot noitnetta yap t’ndid eH
erutxim egnarts a tlef namrehS
,dias neht dna redic sih fo pis a koot namrehS
.nemeltneg degilbo hcuM“
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb ”adlihnurB“si
.emit eht lla deracs os eb t’ndluohs eh detsisni taht niarb sih fo trap a saw erehT
.lla meht gnirettacs ,srecnad fo elcric eht fo elddim eht dnuora sgel dna smra sih devaw eH
.serutcip eht gnikat erew yeht sa
.nogard a fo luos eht yllacificeps erom ,seY“
.redrocer epat eht reh evig dluow eh os
emoceb dah rac niart ehT
.mih ta yltcerid detniop dna
.niart eht fo tuo mih worht ot dediced tsohg eht fi yllaicepsE
.gnicnad ot kcab thgir erew yeht hguone noos tub
.dessih dna nibac reh fo roolf eht no delwarps syob eht ta kool eno koot ehS
,feiler dna esirprus rieht oT
”...hcihw fo gnikaeps dnA
tekcirc nootrac tnarebuxe na dah gab ehT
.lla retfa poocs elbaveilebnu taht ta ecnahc a tog ev’ew tahT !oN“
.mih dniheb demrofer neht ,thgil otni derettacs srecnad eht fo elpuoc a dna
.aremac eht rof desop namrehS dna
gniklaw saw eh noitcerid eht sa
.eromyna ekat ton dluoc eh
.yawa deirrac saw eh erofeb namrehS barg ot gniyrt
.seirots setirw dna
.ria eht otni nees reve dah namrehS tsehgih eht depmuj dna
,revo gnikat stcnitsni loohcs ,dnah sih pu dleh evilC
,dias neht dna dehgual ylliT ”?eguh
kaeb s’namrehS ot revo redrocer epat eht dednetxe eH
”?tekcar taht lla si tahW“
,rac niart eht fo swodahs eht ni gnidih tsohg a saw ereht fi oS
?evilC“ .mih tih ti nehT ?tahw tuB
.eromyna thgir ylf dna ffo ekat t’ndluoc lrig roop ehT .yvaeh oot saw riA
yletaidemmi dootsrednu namrehS
,dias dna htuom sih ot kcab redrocer epat eht thguorb evilC
nihc sih rednu dnah sih gnivom deppots namrehS
,niaga mih guh namrehS tlef eH
.noisacco no eleluku eht yalp dna tniap ot nwonk neeb osla s’eH
,deksa eh mih ot detfihs sucof s’ylliT nehw dna
gnidnif yletanutrofnu erofeb tib a flesmih gnineerP
niart eht fo dnuos eht sa swalc reh htiw tuo dehcaer ehS
namrehS ta dekool ylliT
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ni gnitnirps ekil gnileef diova ot ecap rewols hcum a ta klaw ot dah tub ,mih retfa wollof ot deirt eH
”?taht od ot deen neve yeht dluow yhW“
kcab gnimoc erofeb dnoces a rof thguoht dna
.tuhs ti gnimmals ,rood eht otni ti dekcams dna
,meht fo htob eht drawot devom ylliT
aremac tnatsni llams a thguorb namrehS
,thgir neht ,tfel gnilffunS
”?snaem siht tahw wonk uoy oD
,gnihtemos ees ot detcepxe dah eH
.wodniw eht tuo kool ot edis eht ot
”.gnivil eunitnoc dna dlrow eht ees ot yaw a reh evag tnua ym ,oS .ydob reh ot dnuob saw ehs tub ,reh ni tfel efil hcum os dah adlihnurB
.mih fo tnorf ni sdnah sih gnivaw deirt eH
.KO eb dluow gnihtyreve taht mih llet ot detnaw eH
.emoh kcab teg ot yaw a dnif dna
.desserpmi t’nsaw evilC tuB
kcen s’namrehS fo kcab eht ta gnipeerc gnileef a saw erehT
.semit elpitlum dnahtsrif leets fo sevren s’evilC nees d’eH
redrocer epat eht ffo dekcilc evilC
.eniltuo sih saw ydob sih fo noitrop elbaviecrep ylurt ylno ehT
”,stsohg ruoy rof tnuh ot emiT
.noitagilbo na dah yeht thguoht evilC ,yletarucca erom rO
.demaercs lla yeht neht dnA
niart eht ffo poh d’yeht ,dah yeht ecnahc efas tsrif eht
gnithgil ykoops yltneiciffus dah taht rac niart eht ni stops emos dnuof yeht rehtegoT
.gnileep t’nsi edisni eht no tniap eht nevE
,delriwt dna nups yeht sa dna
.mih htiw eugra yllaer t’ndluoc namrehS
,niart eht evoba erew yehT  .demaercs evilC
”...sediseb dnA .won yb gnihtemos dias evah dluow eh ,rof gnikool saw eh tahw erew ew fI
.neewollaH saw ti togrof I
”!!!HHHHHHHHHHHA“  .thgin eht otni tuo dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.won thgir taht tuoba kniht t’ndluoc namrehS tuB
.stirips otni detfihs dna deremmihs taht
.detcepxe eh naht retteb ti deganam dah yeht tub
”.kcab dna lleh ot pu taeb eb dluohs tI
gniog ro gnitaert-ro-kcirt tuo erew sdik rehto elihW
.dnuorg eht ffo tfil t’ndluoc ehs ,reh dnuof tnua ym nehW
.elbakaerb yrev ,yrev dna
taes tseraen eht ot nar namrehS
,ecnedive eht fo esopsid ot yawa deklaw ehs sA
”?loohcs ta kcab su tnuah dna
ro setatidem eh yas ot mih detcepxe dah namrehS .elpmis os saw
!elpmas dnuos a DNA
.namrehS ot ti gniwohs t’nsaw eh ,saw eh fi rO
.rehtie reetnulov ot swap rieht gnisiar saw puorg rieht ni esle enoyna ekil ton s’tI
.ylevitcnitsni liat sih fo og tel dna
.noitavresbo fo ruoh tsrif eht nihtiw gnihtyna
”,esuoh reh ta srab ydnac ezis-lluf tuo gnivig si naebrettuB .srM draeh I
.niart regnessap yemit dlo na no
.gab kcans a nepo gnillup saw eh taht ees dluoc eh evilC ta revo kool ot tnew eh nehW
.devrennu yletelpmoc gnieb no niaga ecno sucof dluoc namrehS ,ylreporp
.ecneirepxe laerrus eht etiuq saw dekrow niart siht woh nialpxe rotcudnoc eht ot gninetsil teknalb a no gnittiS
llab llams a otni pu delruc dah namrehS
,sreggad sa prahs htob
,wwA“ ,htiw ni demihc namrehS os detnioppasid dekool evilC ”.ogniB“
.nwo sih fo seirots emos etirw ot emit sekam eh
.tfola sksam eht dloh ot srae ro ,tuons ,daeh on saw ereht taht ees dluoc evilC dna namrehS
.delims dna namrehS ot denrut evilC
dexaler seye s’ti sa
knuhcak-knuhcak-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hc-hC .rac niart eht ot rood eht nepo nworht dah namrehS sa tsuj dneirf sih drawot nar dna pu tog eH .od ot gniyrt saw namrehS tahw tuo derugif eh nehw dennuts llits saw evilC ”!won
.deticxe siht mih nees reven dah namrehS
.ypeerc saw rac niart eht ,stsohg fo ytilibissop eht tuohtiw nevE
.goD fO tsohG ehT dellac
,tuo dnuof nosrep gnorw eht fI
.flesym wonk ylthgir t’nod I“ ”?woH“ ”.peY“
,wonk’y ,snogard t’nerA
.noitarepsaxe ni daeh sih koohs ohw
,lliw sih tsniaga gnirettahc kaeb
.rac niart eht fo dne rehto eht morf gnimoc thgil egnaro tniaf a ees dluoc namrehS ,noisiv sih fo renroc eht fo tuo dnA
”.ti tuoba gnikniht tsuj srehtaef ym lla elffur ot egru na teg I
rac enigne eht fo pot eht hguorht desahp yeht sa
ecaf s’drazil eht was dna
.ti ees t’ndluoc syob owt eht saw ti revetahw tub
.niart eht fo traeh eht otni nwod dna
”adlihnurB“ saw sihT
.niart siht no stirips on era erehT
.toom eb dluow sgniht esoht gniyas tlef eh ,denruter thgil egnaro eht sa tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
rof evas ,ytpme saw rac niart ehT
”?regnad elbirroh ni er’ew tahT“
.yas I tahw naem I dna naem I tahw yas I taht
”.gnihtemos ro staes eht deretslohpuer tsuj ev’thgim yehT
nihc sih ot dnah a tup evilC
.ni evilC tel ot hguone sgniw sih dedlofnu namrehS dna guh a mih evig ot tnew eH
.staes eht htaenrednu sevlesmeht dih dna
.nwod flesmih mlac dna yrt ot snolat dnih sih ta wehc ot nageb dna
.ti no pitgniw a tup t’ndluoc eh dna gnorw ylbirret gnihtemos saw erehT
.dnats ot tnew dna taes eht rednu morf tuo flesmih dellup eH
.thginot meht morf yawa peek ot dediced dah stsohg eht dalg saw tub ,detnioppasid dneirf sih ees ot detah eH
.deirt evilC tahw fo yna ot tcaer t’ndid eh tuB
dna regnad yna ni t’nerew yeht tahT