hsauqs nroca eht fo flah ’sakuL pu dleh eH
nees reve dah oehT kcub emosdnah tsom eht eb ot tuo denrut regnarts ehT
,hteet gnikcalc hguorht dias dna derevihs oehT
.egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna noitciF degnaF yb
si yrots s’yadoT dna
?tuoba siht saw tahW
.sruoy em llet uoy fi ,yrots ym uoy llet ll’I
,krad eht morf dias sakuL neht
”?gnihtemos ro nap a deen uoy t’noD“
,eldnah eht otni kcab edalb eht pilf t’ndluoc eh
.kcub eht ta derats oehT ”?syad ,tiaW“
ruf s’kcub eht gnikram trid eht ees dluoc eh
.daehliart a raen daeha ffo llup a saw erehT
.tip eht fo egde kcirb eht tsniaga pu deltsen
.ti nmad ,yadirF saw tI ?skrej
,egats siht ta reppep dna tlas dedda evah dluow eh yllamroN
,erif eht fo thgil eht dna oehT ot resolc saw eh taht won tuB
pu doots sakuL sa ,sselhceeps dehctaw eH
.retnec eht morf thgir etib gib a nekat dna hsauqs eht otni elzzum sih fo dne eht kcuts ydaerla dah sakuL
.daeh sih fo pot eht ta gnibbur dna pu kcab gnidnats ,delrans eh ”,hcuO“
a tuo gnidloh ,regnarts eht ot denrut dna
eno hcae pu dekcip ylluferac eH
”.tnet ym ni eidooh artxe na evah I“
.yawyna niks eht tae t’ndid yllareneg uoy esuaceb
,dnah ’sakuL ni gnihtemos fo tuo dellips thgil neddus a fo llA
.desufnoc kool ot nrut s’oehT saw ti woN
,yawa decnalg eh dna knip denrut srae s’kcub emosdnah eht fo gninil ehT
stnap sih no ffo edalb eht depiw eH
”.wor a ni thgin htdnasuoht eht rof sseletad gnieb tuoba yrrow toN
.ylsselesu desolc dna denepo tsuj htuom sih daetsni tub ,dnim sih fo eceip a mih evig ot ydaer
”.yrots gnol a adnik ,hu s’tI“
,gnikaeps dehsinif dah oehT emit eht yB
.hcum oot elttil a depmiks I sseug I tub ,yvaeh era sgniht esohT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
no kcab pot eht tes eH
,deksa regnarts eht
?thgilhsalf ruoy tuoba tahW“
,sehsal gnol htiw
.efink tneb sih pu gnikcip erofeb ,gnikooc eht no kcehc ot pu tas eh sa gel ’sakuL dettap dna revo denael oehT .dehgis sakuL
.hsauqs sih ffo pot eht tuc ot tneiciffus eb dluohs llits ti tuB .deniuR
”.em ekil kcub ,hu ,elttil ynit a ta eciwt skool eno on dnA
.edis s’revird eht otni edils ot nwod gnikcud erofeb taes regnessap eht otni gab sih dessot dna rood rac sih denepo eH
y ,hU“ .daeh sih no thgiew artxe eht ot desu teg ot mih rof dna ylreporp laeh ot emit stnalpmi eht evig ot
.flah hsauqs nwo sih pu dekcip dna dehgual oehT .gnitae tpek dna
,ylpeed delahni dna seye sih desolc oehT
,efink sih pu kcab gnikciP .tuo derettuts eh
.leehw eht dniheb tog neht dna kcapkcab sih ot txen taes regnessap eht otno meht dessot eH
”?hsauqs dna noino taht sI“
,noino eht ekil tsuJ“
enips s’oehT nwod tnew llirht A
.sakuL ta gnikool dna nwod kcab gnilttes erofeb nrut retrauq rehtona hcae meht gnivig
drawA ltoyoC a now sah ohw
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,deilper kcub eht ”,sakuL“
,dnaltroP ot nwod elttaeS morf ekih ot desoppus saw I
.erif eht fo thgil eht ni mih fo weiv doog a oehT gnivig
.nruter ’sakuL dedlareh sesruc derettum dna sehcnarb gnikcarc
.tuo tog yllanif oehT ”,haey ,hU“
,daeh sih revo no ti dellup dna taes kcab eht fo tuo eidooh a tog eH
enod saw eh nehW
.spu-piz yub dna srevo-llup ruoy lla fo dir teg ,retteb ssap ot tnaw uoy fi ,od dluohs uoy gniht tsriF
.hcamots ’sakuL morf gnimoc lworg duol a yb ffo tuc saw ylper siH “—sknahT“
retal setunim wef A
.tnet remraw eht fo reffo eht no pu sakuL ekat dluohs eh dezilaer dna niaga derevihs eH
,resolc denael regnarts ehT
.saw eh suovren woh ees t’ndluoc sakuL os krad saw ti dalg saw oehT dna
.noitseuq deksanu s’oehT draeh d’eh fi sa ,dias eh
,ylkciuq dias oehT
.edalb eht ot egamad eht revo dehgis oehT
.gnisruc sakuL draeh eh dna deppans sehcnarB
”?uoy htiw tis I fi dniM“
”.owt rof hguone gib si tnet ym tuB“
ecnelis detnetnoc ni ereht yal sakuL
.ereh pu evird ot tsuj mih nekat dah ti gnol woh fo gnikniht
.moordeb sih ni enola gnittis ton ,kcub toh a htiw etad toh a rof ydaer gnitteg eb dluohs eH
.ni ekih ot mih ekat dluow ti syad erom ruof ro eerht eht ti ekam reven dluow sakuL ,doof tuohtiW
.yawa daeh sih detlit dna
degnis saw hsauqs eht fo edistuo ehT
esuaceb ,mih rof gib oot raf saw ti taht doog yllautca saw tI
,raef sih htiw etihw gniggalf pu deppop liat sih mih dniheB
.hsauqs eht fo pot eht dessim efink sih dna esirprus ni depmuj oehT
.flah ni hsauqs nroca eht tuc ot efink eht desu oehT
,elgna na ta nwod kcab delttes eh
,kcub emosdnah a ro eod toh a htiw bulc a ta eb dluohs I
.edis eht detned ylisae ti dna
.seye sih gnirevoc
”.yaw eht yb ,oehT m’I“ .dnah
.erif sih ta oehT nioj ot revo emoc d’eh
tnet sih ni snoops ekil slisnetu dah ylbaborp sakuL taht dezilaer eh yldetaleB
dekcip d’eh tops eht ot tsesolc tip erif kcirb eht ni
.saw eh sa toh sa neve
.oehT gnidnilb
.seiradnuob tcepser ot demees dna
”.srats eht rednu peels ot gniog tsuj saw I
won hguone krad saw tI
.rehto eht neht dna reltna eno gnihcated ,detsiwt dna esab eht debbarg eH ”.sgniht diputS“
.slirtson sih gniralf dna
.mih dniheb ssenkrad eht fo tuo emac eciov elam peed a
.tnecs eht ta gnitavilas
.sreltna elbavomer ot stifeneb erew ereht taht os did eh sa gnitcelfer
.seirettab fo tuo naR“
,sakuL sdrawot dnah-fooh a tuo dleh oehT ”?laeD
?snart gnieb uoy htiw od ot evah ti seoD“
.tnet ’sakuL sdrawot yaw sih gnileef nageb dna gab sih pu dekcip oehT ,ylsuovreN
.kaeps ot evren eht pu derehtag sakuL elihw gnitiaw ,ylteiuq tas oehT
.yawa dekool dna niaga daeh sih dekcud sakuL ”,haeY“
,emit sih koot oehT
.gnikooc sih no eye na peek t’ndluoc eh taht raf os ton tub
.kcab sih otno nwod dial dna
.sgel sih gnissorc
.stops fo kcip sih dah eh detciderp eh sA
?drah os eb ot evah gnitad enilno did yhW
.sniatnuom eht otni
. . .ot ereh pu emac uoy os ,thginot enola emoh eb ot tnaw t’ndid uoy“ ,dias sakuL ”,oS“
.neercs eht ekorb tsomla regnif deppit-fooh sih drah os gnippat ,enohp sih no ppa eht desolc oehT
.enohp evisnepxe sih gniniur ksir ot hguone yrgna ton tub ,sey ,dam saw eH
,denaorg dna hcnilf sih deciton sakuL
.ylleb sih dettap dna seye sih desolc sakuL ”.nam ,yaw oN“
.uoy denaol I eidooh taht otni dellor nettog dah ti sseuG
.sreyal retuo eht kcab deleep eh sa
.ekawa yltneg mih ekahs ot gnidnetni ,sakuL revo denael eh
,yad taht htoot teews a dah eh fi purys elpam dna ,yramesor ,nomannic emos neve ro
.noino eht debbarg sakuL
.tnemrednow flah dna feiler flah fo hgual a tuo tel oehT ”.esruoc fO“
.lla retfa ,yaw siht emit eht ssap ot aedi sih neeb dah tI
hcus syug erew yhW
.rotcoD eht fo evol ykeeg sih tuoba yllaicepsE
tneb edalb eht htiw ecnis ,mih ot txen trid eht ni efinktekcop eht yal eH
,srevo-llup yub t’nod sliatetihw yug-siC
.oehT ot esolc desserp eh sa ydob sih fo taeh eht tlef neht dna dnuora gnitfihs sakuL draeh eH
rettam t’ndid taht tub ,erif eht ot resolc saw ti ecnis
erofeb desu d’eh setis pmac emos erew liart eht pu selim net tuobA
.sseug I ,daeh ym raelc ot detnaw tsuj I
uoy rof daer ,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ saw sihT
skcirb eht no hsauqs eht tes eH
,elims a oehT dehsalf
.dnah derefforp s’oehT gnikahs ylmrif dna tuo gnihcaer
,gnip a htiw skcirb eht ffo decnuob edalb ehT
.esir eht fo pot eht ta
.nruter ot sakuL rof detiaw eh elihw gnikooc sih ot dednet oehT
tuo dewollib maetS
,llew yllaer ti gnikat sakuL saw ylno toN
,hu ,lleW“ ”?ot desoppuS“
”.yaw eht ni teg yeht nehw ffo sreltna ruoy ekat nac uoy suolaej fo dnik m’I“
.gnilims saw eh edisni tub ,deggurhs oehT
.etib gib a koot oehT
si koob tsewen sih dna
”.erif eht ta kcab ,tuo ti derugif ydaerla I esuaC
,tip eht edisni meht tup eH
edis sih no dellor kcub eht ,gnilimS
.oehT ot txen nwod elttes ot sgel sih dessorc dna
,yrc a htiw kcab llef eH
”.hcnarb a ni thguac tsuj sreltnA .ko m’I“
”.gans a otni nar fo dnik I
.gnipmac gniog saw eH
.daeh sih koohs dna smra sih dessorc eh sa delkcuhc oehT
neht dna egdirf eht fo tuo rettub emos deggans eh rood eht tuo yaw sih nO
,rekih deraperp a hcus yhw derednow eH
.regnif defooh a htiw edis sih ot trid eht ni gniward ,dias sakuL
,krad eht otni dehsinav eh sa tixe suoirolg a neeb evah dluow tI
ereht tog eh nehW
”.dah reve ev’I laem tseb eht saw tahT“
.gninepo eht otni gab sih morf rettub fo ebuc eht deppolp neht dna
.hcamots sih ot pu dnah a gnittup
.gninepo eht fo tuo dellor rettub dna hsauqs detsaor fo amora gnorts a dna maetS
”.tsrif uoy llet ot evah I gnihtemos s’ereht ,hu tub ,seY“
trihstaews pu-piz a oehT dednah ylsseldrow dna
trid eht no sehcni wef a revo ttub sih gnitoocs
”dnerT eht gnikcuB“
.nur ecitcarp a fo dnik si pirt sihT
”,taht ekil ti tup uoy nehw ,lleW“ ”?enola . . .eb
yletaidemmi tsomlA
.rehtruf llits mih dexaler dekih eh sa mih dnuora sevael eht hguorht gniltsur dniw eht fo dnuos eht neve tub
,thgil gnikcap tnaem kcab seno no gnihtyreve luah ot gnivah
.hgual a tuo tel
.noisicedni htiw nezorf llits saw ohw
,tnet ecin a dna sehtolc mraw artxe htiw eno
.tsehc sih fo ruf eht delffur dna
”?enola ,emoh ta eb ot tnaw t’ndid I esuaceb enola eb ot sniatnuom eht ot pu gnimoc naht rediputS“
.tuo tips ot deganam oehT lla saw ”,haG“
.hguone ecin s’tI“ .derepsihw eh ”,oN“ .deplug oehT
.eson ’sakuL no ssik a tnalp ot nwod denael eh dna mih hguorht tnew llirht A .dettimda eh
kcar ’sakuL fo dne raf eht morf gnimoc senit gnol eht fo eno gnivah diova ot edis eht ot egdod ot evah ot oehT gnisuac
,sdrawA yraretiL OEL owt dna
,efink eht htiw nwod gnihsals saw eh sa tsuJ
.yawyna flesmih rof tsuj hcum oot neeb evah dluow tI .deksa oehT
.pu ti piz ot moor evah llits dna
,tnet a dekcap t’ndah oehT etsah sih nI
,toh yrev saw kcub ehT
,swodniw eht yb deppihw seert neerg eht sA
”.gniklat noitavrats ruoy tsuj s’taht kniht I“ .dehgual neht
,elbisiv saw tnet rehto eno ylnO
.pmur sih no dnal ot kcab llef eh dna skeehc s’oehT dedoolf taeH
.snaej dna tekcaj kcalb pu-piz a erow kcub ehT
,sakuL htiw xes evah ot detnaw yllautca eh erus t’nsaw eh ,llew ,sulP
efink sih pu dekcip eh tnemssarrabme sih revoc oT
.kcapkcab ytpme sih fo pot no gniyal enohp sih dettops dna
,yllautcA .delbmurg sakuL
,enola eb ot ereh pu emoc dah regnarts eht fi ,yhw niaga gnirednow
”.uoy t’ndid ,doof fo tuo nar uoY“
.tae ot ytic eht ot kcab tog eh llit tiaw tsuj dluoc eh tub
.hsauqs eht fo edis rehtie no meht tes dna
moor llams eht dnuora decnalg eH
,nedrag eht fo tuo snoino wef a dna hsauqs nroca na
hgis gib a tuo tel sakuL nehw eceip sih fo flah tuoba netae ylno d’eH
.sakuL ta sevooh sih hguorht tuo ecnalg a deksir eH
,tsael ta ,og d’eH
,pu kcab denethgiarts dah kcub reggib ehT
ylwols dehcterts dna
,raey tsrif eht rof ylno stnemhcatta ledom tsellamS
,snoino eht kcehc neht dna
stneicnA eht fo lautiR
etispmac eht dehcaer eh emit eht yb pu ekih eht morf eros erew sgel dna sevooh siH
.ylneve dekooc yeht taht os
.mih dehcuot neve oehT erofeb nepo deppans seye s’kcub ehT
pu til seye ’sakuL
,sreltna fo gnikaepS
.tahwemos demmid thgil gnidnilb ehT ”.yrros ,hO“
”.syad ni gnivah eb ll’I laem tsrif eht rof edart ni od nac I tsaeL .emoclew er’uoY“
,oehT ta kool ot dnah-fooh eno htiw pu daeh sih depporp dna
,sdnah-fooh sih ni ecaf sih tser ot drawrof denael sakuL
.egde eht ni tned gib a gnittup
.eidooh niht s’oehT hguorht thgiarts welb dna
”,diputs s’tI“ ”.nrut ruoY“
,resolc devom dah regnarts ehT
?em htiw detrilf uoy nehw wenk uoY“
.mrif doots d’ehs tub ,sreltna reggib mih evig ot noegrus sih deggeb dah oehT
.edisni gnillaf morf pot eht peek ot hguone saw taht dna ,elgna na ta ti tuc d’eh ,revewoH
.snart saw eh tuo gnidnif ot tcaer dluow kcub eht woh suovren saw oehT ,revewoH
.saw ti thguoht eh noitcerid eht ni detniop eh tub
.ereh pu yaw sih no daor eht gnola ro stol eht fo yna ni dekrap srac rehto yna nees t’ndah eh ,ti tuoba thguoht eh taht woN
.ylneve dekooc yeht taht os snoino eht etator ylluferac ot pit efink eht gnisu ,dias oehT ”,epoN“
.sakuL ta revo decnalg dna seye sih denepo oehT
,rac eht fo tuo tog dna dekrap eH
.pu mraw ot erif eht yb skcirb eht no ti tes dna hsauqs eht tuo dellup eH
sdees eht tuo poocs ot efink eht desu eh ,pot eht edisa gnitteS
.kcapkcab eht no gniggurhs erofeb meht dehcattaer dna taes regnessap eht ffo sih dellup oehT
.eidooh revo llup s’oehT ta derutseg sakuL ”?woH“
.dehctaw eh sa daeh sih gnikcoc
”.sevooH rotcoD fo snurer gnihctaw enola emoh ta gnittis ton
.smlap sih dedlacs dna sdnah sih revo nar rettuB
nrut a selbategev gnitsaor eht fo eerht lla evig dluoc eh taht os pu dehsup dna
,dettimda oehT ”,oot ,eM“ ”.ereh
.enod saw hsauqs ehT
oehT .tnet sih fo pot derevoc epat-kcud eht ta pu decnalg eH
”.kcab thgir eB“ ”.eruS“
.laem yna fo trap tseb eht saw sihT
erif gnildniwd eht ta dekool eH
.thgil mid eht ni dehsalf hteet ’sakuL ”.sknahT“
.tnet reed-owt sih fo noitcerid eht ni krad eht otni ffo detturts neht
,seert eht hguorht tnet eht ees regnol on dluoc eh taht
”.lla retfa kcap yrettab degrahc-ralos a fo esahcrup taht no pu krelc eht nekat evah dluohs I
.dnah a pu dleh sakuL
.don a htiw dias sakuL ”,esnes sekaM“
?esle erehwemos morf ereh dekih eh daH
.werdhtiw sakuL sa s’oehT depparcs sregnif deppit-fooh siH
,ssa ’sakuL no dexif seye s’oehT
”.emoh kcab niart eht hctac neht
”.ffo llef sreltna rieht litnu retniw eht flah rof no meht teg ot elba eb t’ndluow yeht
sreyal sih lla hguorht welb dniw dloc fo tsug a sa derevihs eH
,egde eno no niks eht kcab gnileeP
.sracs wen sih ta gnillup yllufniap
.yna kcap ot detcelgen d’eh esuoh eht evael ot etsah sih ni tub ,skciphtoot htiw no ti dloh d’eh yllamroN
.remraw ylbaredisnoc tlef ydaerla oehT
.taorht sih tsniaga ylgguns detser ti litnu pu
.sedisni etihw ,tfos s’noino eht ta gnipmohc nageb eh etib a ekat ot moor hguone saw ereht sa noos sa
.ti otni gnihtolc gniffuts detrats dna gab ytpme eht debbarg eh
yhsup neeb t’ndah sakuL raf oS
.efink eht htiw dluoc eh tseb sa pu dehsinif dna deggurhs tsuj oehT taht
ytic eht fo tuo evow eH
.sakuL ot tsesolc noino eht fo daeh eht deppat yltneg dna efink eht pu dekcip oehT
.dehsulb eh sa mraw gnitteg elzzum dna srae sih tlef oehT
hsauqs fo lufhtuom a dnuora elbigilletninu gnihtemos delbmum sakuL
edalb eht fo talf eht htiw hsauqs nroca eht fo hself eht ta dekop eH
”.si tI .sey ,yllautcA“
.ffo pot eht tuc ot gniraperp
”.sedisni eht tae dna ffo sniks eht leep tsuj uoy ,enod er’yeht ecnO
.thgilhsalf a ro doof ekil scisab evah ot mees t’ndid
noynac a pu dedaeh neht dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
?doof sih revo gniloord kcub siht saw yhW
.pot eht ffo detfil dna mets s’hsauqs eht debbarg oehT txeN
.krad eht otni yawa delbmuts dna teef sih ot tog sakuL
,oehT ecaf ylluf ot denrut dna kcab tas sakuL ”?hO“
.detneuqerf eh erehwyreve dehsats strihstaews ycnegreme dah llits eh tub ,sreyal ssel raew ot gnivah neeb dna
.elbissop erew taht fi ,esolc pu emosdnah erom neve saw kcub ehT
.hguorht sregnif sih nur ot detnaw oehT taht ruf nat gnikool-tfos dna ,seye kcalb gib
.hcum os etiuq ot timda ot tnaem t’ndah eH .ecaf sih gnidih
.sesruc delffum dna sehcnarb gnippans fo sdnuos eht yb tnet eht ot kcab pirt ’sakuL wollof ot elba
”,tae dna edistuo eht ffo leep
.gnimlehwrevo ylraen emaceb kcub emosdnah siht morf eelf ot egru eht dna
.gnissap no spit oehT gnivig saw eh
.dehcti llits yeht tub ,ylecin gnilaeh erew yehT
.hsauqs eht ekat ot edisa leep noino eht dessot eh dna
.snoino gnitsaor sih fo tnorf ni sehsa eht otni hsauqs eht deltsen neht dna
oehT denaol d’eh eidooh eht fo reppiz eht llup ot dnah rehto sih htiw drawrof dehcaer eh dna
.sraey owt ni etad a no neeb t’nevah I taht detartsurf m’I ,llew ,esuaceb enoyreve morf yawa teg ot ereh pu m’I“
.mih dniheb trid eht otni gud sreltna sih fo senit ehT
.sreltna rieht revo ffuts revo-llup eht teg t’ndluoc yeht esuaceb strihs pu-nottub dna seidooh pu-piz yub ot dah lla sdneirf yug-sic siH
.pal sih ni sdnah-fooh sih gnitser
.cirbaf eht no sreltna sih hctac ot ton luferac ,edisni debmilc yldrawkwa oehT ”.ni emoc ,ni emoC
,esop ’sakuL dekcimim oehT woN
”.renetsil tnellecxe na dna ,kooc taerg a ,elbaroda er’uoY
.ereh pu emac I yhw wonk t’nod I“
.deraperp retteb yna saw eh taht toN
.wollip eht ffo decnuob ti erehw deb sih rof gnimia
,mraw saw hsauqs eht taht woN
”.gninrom eht ni noitats niart eht ot edir a uoy evig nac I“
.seert eht yb neddih tsomla dna etis pmac eht fo dne raf eht ta dehctip
.gnirps txen gnitrats liart lluf od ot gninnalp m’I
”?gniod uoy era tahW“
,pots ot deksa eh fi taht saw tcnitsni siH
.derettam ti taht toN
.ssensuovren sih nwod hsauq ot gniyrt
.nepo gnipag htuom
.htuom sih ni detlem hself s’hsauqs eht rettub tsuj htiw neve tub
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb
”?laem ym erahs ot ekil uoy dluow ,mU“
.sdnah sih no tser ot kcab denael dna dehgis sakuL
.sdees eht tuo poocs ylismulc ot efink eht fo edalb eht desu eH
.oehT ot txen tis ot devom neht dna tnet eht fo roolf eht no nretnal eht tes sakuL
”.etuc er’uoy dna ,syug ekil I
denediw elims ’sakuL
remraw neeb d’eh enoretsotset detrats eh ecnis revE
.rehtruf yna tnew sgniht erofeb wonk ot devresed sakuL
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,thgin yadirF s’tI
sniks rieht morf pu detfaw noino gnitsaor fo tnecs eht
”,suoiciled llems snoino ruoY“
.tnet eht fo dne eno no sgniht ’sakuL fo elip a otno ti gnissot ,ffo ti koot dna eidooh ’sakuL deppiznu eH
,meht teg dluoc eh sa erif eht morf raf sa
.noitcefrep ot denworb erew hcihw
.reisae boj siht edam evah dluow taht
edis eht ot delwarc dna nwod gab sih tas eH
”,tneinevnoc adnik si tI“
trihstaews rehto sih potrevo no ti tup ot elba ylisae saw eh
.taeh eht yb detceffa t’nerew regnif hcae fo sdne eht ta sbun nitarek kciht ehT .edis rehtie no
,sdnah-fooh sih htiw smra sih debbur dna derevihs eH
,deid dna derekcilf nretnal eht ,neht thgiR
.eidooh sih no gniggans
.sevooh sih ni ecaf sih gnidih revo depmuls llits saw ohw
.yrettab erom eno dnuof I“
.edisni dnuora gnitoor kcub eht raeh dluoc eh
.ecnalg deltrats a sakuL evag oehT ”,tiaW“
.tuhs tnet eht piz dluoc sakuL taht os
,gnosdrib hcum t’nsaw ereht raey fo emit sihT
,strohs sih evoba tuo dedurtorp liat degde-etihw siH
,setispmac ruof yreve rof tip eno ylno saw erehT
,neerg a dewohs taht llaw sih no retsop a revo nar seye siH
,yllairotaripsnoc eciov sih derewol sakuL ”,sulP“ ”.hO“
.saw yllaer ti niht woh tsuj ecneirepxe morf wenk eh tub ,gab sih ni tam gnipmac pu dellor
doof sih ni dessorgne os saw kcub eht tub ,ksa ot gnidnetni sakuL ot denrut eH
.oga shtnom xis neeb dah yregrus ehT
seye sih gnisolc
”,llams os era sruoy ykcul er’uoY“
.xaler ot gnitrats flesmih leef dluoc eh
.reltna na fo esab eht gnola fooh a nar yldednim-tnesba dna dehgis oehT
”.tnet a evah t’nod uoy deciton I“
.evres tsrif ,emoc tsrif erew taht
.noino sih fo setib wef tsal eht pu gnihsinif saw kcub eht sa
yawa gninrub ylirrem saw erif sih erofeb gnol t’nsaw tI
”,haeY“ ”?tnet ruoy tahT“
.snoino owt eht rof moor ekam ot yawa gol gninrub a dehsup eh kcits a htiw nehT
eslupmi nO .tserof yfael
relleK nosidaM yb
.ssenkrad otni meht gnignulp
.denediw seye s’oehT
.meht no nihc sih gnitser dna tsehc sih ot seenk sih gnillup
,edis sti otno hsauqs eht dellor dna efink tekcop gib sih tuo dellup eh
.etib hcae gnirovas
esohT .yrots ruoy gniraeh retfa kcuf ytip a ton si siht raews I ,oslA“
”?ti tegrof uoy diD
,enod gniht elohw eht dah eh litnu tiaw neve t’ndid sakuL
.taerg llems did yllaer yehT
.raelc yrev tseretni sih edam dah dna
.dekniw eh ”,eciohc ruoY“
,hsauqs eht dekop dna snoino eht no dekcehc dna denrut oehT
,duht a dna esruc duol a yb dewollof yletaidemmi saw ti taht tpecxe
,remocwen eht ta eralg ot denrut oehT
,relleK nosidaM yb
.stnemhcatta reltna sih hctarcs ot pu dehcaer eh ,yltnesbA
,mih ta derats oehT ”?did uoY“
.sakuL ot revo hsauqs nedlog eht dessap eh sa dias oehT
.gnirob s’tI .taht deirt ev’I tuB .flesym yb bulc eht ot og tsuj dluoc I wonk I ,sey dnA“
erif eht ot txen nwod deppolp eH
.gnitae dehsinif oehT sa
,moor eht ssorca ti dessot eh ,erusaem doog rof ,nehT
.kool desufnoc a oehT gnivig saw eH
.elims a htiw dias eh ”,emac uoY“
.ereht pu esle enoyna eb t’ndluohs ereht raey eht fo emit sihT
.deppop dna deppans derehtag d’eh sehcnarb eht ni pas mih ediseB
.tey dloc taht nettog t’ndah ti tub
.edud ,yawaevig daeD“
.pu gnikool tuohtiw fooh s’oehT koohs dna pu dehcaer sakuL ”.eniF“
.hsauqs eht fo pot eht ffo dewas neht dna
,emarfrood eht ffo decnuob yeht dna sreltna wen sih fo thgieh eht rof hguone wol kcud t’ndid eH
.sakuL morf hgual ylleb a werd tahT .detrons oehT
.seveels gnol-oot eht pu dehsup eH
.’sakuL fo dne eht tsniaga thgir dednal elzzum s’oehT esuaceb ,devom evah tsum sakuL
.erif eht ni yltcerid meht kooc nac uoY“
.epat kcud htiw dehctap yledurc neeb dah taht
,dias oehT ”,dnaltroP ot selim ytfif rehtona s’ti wonk uoY“ .derepsihw eh
.krad eht ni dnuora gnilbmuts uoy deciton I
.snaej gnikih sih yb denifed ylecin
,dewollaws dna dewehc oehT
.repmac rehto eht morf yawa
,tsafkaerb rof hsauqs eht fo trap dna noino dnoces eht evas ot gninnalp neeb d’eH
”.suoiciled sllems tI“
.tnew ti woh ees dna
.deksa sakuL ”?dloc uoy era ,hO“
,noino sih deruoved sakuL elihW
.dniw citcra siht fo emos tsniaga tcetorp ot tnet a evah did eh tub
.seye sih rednu selcric kcalb gib eht ees dna
.ezag sih tem sakuL sa ezorf oehT
.sehtolc sih fo pot no kcap sih otni meht gniffuts
.thginot eussi na saw taht taht ton
”.doog sllems taht ,woW“
.ssik gnol a rof ni mih dellup sakuL sa tsetorp t’ndid eH
.ereh tuo eno ylno eht eb d’I thguoht I rebotcO gnieB“
”?gnipmac emac uoy erofeb rennid teg ot elba ton uoy ereW“
.skcirb toh eht tsniaga detser yeht erehw
.gninepo reppiz a fo dnuos a saw erehT ”?sakuL ,olleH“
,dna dum ekil dellems taht
.peelsa nellaf dah kcub reggib eht thguoht eH
”,dnim t’nod I .on ,hu ,I“
.dnim t’nod I“ ”?dnim t’nod uoY
.aedi doog a neeb dah sihT
,sevooh sih ot tog eh sa daeh sih koohs oehT
.smra sih no ruf eht tih ria dloc eht sa gnirevihs
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,niht a evah did eH
.denaorg oehT ”,eniF“ ”.tsrif uoY“
”dnerT eht gnikcuB“:yojne esaelP
”.sknaht ,lleW“ ”.suoicileD“
,nrub ot erif eht ni meht gnissot yb sniks noino dna hsauqs dedracsid eht pu denaelc d’eh retfA
.dne-raer ’sakuL fo sevruc tfos eht gnithgilhgih dna galf a ekil gnivaw
.deralf slirtson gib sih dna pu deppop daeh ’sakuL
.spitregnif sih htiw pirg a teg ot elba saw eh erofeb tnemom a rof htrof dna kcab ti delgguj eh ”,toh ,toH“
.enod era eseht erofeb ruoh rehtona tsael ta eb ot gniog s’ti ,lleW“
.raelc saw tsacerof rehtaew eht tub
.gnissim er’yeht tahw wonk t’nod nwod uoy denrut ohw slrig dna syug
,rebotcO eb thgim tI
”,sruoy si noino taht ,ereH“
.tuo remmats ot deganam eh lla saw ”,haey-y-
.trid eht no ecaps ytpme na ot txen gnittis kcapkcab ynit nwo sih ta neht dna
.erif eht ot resolc gnitoocs
.htmraw saw htmraW .rettam oN
hsauqs toh eht pu kcip ot sdnah-fooh sih fo hcae fo spitregnif eht desu dna tip erif eht fo egde eht no nwod efink eht tes eH
.won ereht tuo lla ti worht llew sa thgim ,lleW
.erif eht otni gnirats ,tnelis llef eH
.cirbaf eht no dnuos gnihsoohw a edam tsuj tsif sih tub ,llaw tnet eht no kconk ot deirt oehT
.flesmih sakuL saw ereht neht dnA
.taht tcepser dluow sakuL
,reihsuc gnihtyna evah t’ndid ylbaborp sakuL
”.elppa na ekil edisni eht tae tsuj nac uoy neht dna sreyal retuo eht ffo leeP“
.naelc oot enon dekool ,erifpmac sih fo thgil mid eht ni neve
.sega rof liarT tserC cificaP eht ekih ot detnaw ev’I“
skram erutcnup llams fo yteirav a ni derevoc erew tnet eht fo pot eht dna reppiz eht dnuora aera ehT
,seye sih denepo kcub ehT
,sakuL sdrawot erom denrut
,daehrevo sehcnarb neesnu eht hguorht dehsur dniw ehT
,naorg a htiw dias sakuL ”,taerg eb d’tahT“
.erifpmac a trats ot sgol dna sgiwt rehtag ot tnew dna tops gnipmac a ni nwod gab sih tes eH
.nretnal ynit a pu gnidloh sakuL ees ot eralg eht tsniaga deknilb oehT
”,did I“ .daeh sih gnuh kcub ehT ”.haeY“