gnisiar selkcah sih
.ysatnaf dna ,iFicS ,rorroh setirw yltsom eH
,kcab elihw a siht rotcod eht dlot dah eH
,wenk tac a denwo sah ohw enoyna taht yaw taht ni ,wenk regoR
.did ti revetahw gniod saw koot eh llip taht
.rotinom eht fo maelg detcelfer mid eht ni
.doolb sih detsat dna
.srepsihw eroM
.yldeirruh nwod ti elbbog neht dna
,keew rep yrots wen eno htiw
.recnac fo deid emos dna dlo erew emoS
.yaw lufgninaem yna ni ton tsael ta ,elpoep fo tol a
snoziroH kaelB dna
.deffup lla liat sih dna
.saw eh yob doog a tahw mih gnillet eciov ecin a saw ereht dna
.degnahc sdnuos gnilwem ehT
.riahc ysae s’regoR ni
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tac-yderacs a fo ssel mih ekam ot
ni dnuof eb osla nac skrow siH
,yldnuos os peelsa nellaf dna ylkciuq os ereht revo tog hctarcS dah woH
:nosaes ykoops s’raey siht ot
ksed s’regoR rednu saw ti revetahW .tsenoh eb ot
boR tsoh-oc ym fo flaheb no dnA
.regoR tib ro dehctarcs reven dah
elttob llip sih nwod ekat dna flehs eht ot pu hcaer d’eH
.gnikraB .gniniartesuoH
.step rof stac htiw yug baL nedloG gib a fo ynori eht ot dne on s’erehT
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.noisiv sih fo renroc-eht-fo-tuo tsuj erehwemos morf emoc ot demees tI
.hctarcS naht rehto enoyna morf noitnetta laer yna teg t’ndid regoR ,llitS .taC
pu delruc hctarcS ees ot ylno
.sserP taotS retsiniS yb
.pal sih no gnipeelS .dnuora syawla erew yehT .kaep sih ta stac neetfif dah eH
,enotS semaJ yb ”smelborP taC“
.kcab wap sih deknay
.seveeJ elttil fo yromem eht gnitaehc saw eh ekiL .layarteb
,erofeb dehctarcs tog sah tac a denwo s’ohw enoynA
dehctarcs…llew hctarcS ,tniop eno tA
.secils eseehc sti htiw
dna yaw taht ni tac ecin a syawla saw hctarcS tub
hctarcS ta revo decnalg eH
.yug layol a saw eH
goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,enola t’nsaw eh taht srednimer gnirrup elttiL
.niaga gel sih dehsurb gnihtemoS
tuo ekam ylerab dluoc regoR
.niaga sgel sih dekorts dna delwem-
.nettik yarg eno htiw oga sraey detrats tI
.suoixna yrev regoR edam thguoht eht ,tsenoh eb oT
.gel sih dehsurb sgniht elpuoc rehtonA .thgie nehT
enotS semaJ yb
daerD ni dehsilbup
.nosrep tac a saw regoR
eciov eht ot resolc netsil ot rood eht tuhs ot detnaw eH .suoixna regoR edam tahT
sa gaw dluow liat siH
,kcab gniog neeb evah dluow srae sih dna
.devol saw eh taht dna
lllllworg peed a dna
,goD fo ecioV eht no
?htrow si ti naht elbuort erom evol ew tep a ekam dluow taht noitartsurf fo tnuoma yna ereht si tuB
moor eht ssorca decnalg dna
sdrawkcab elttil a dils eH
peelsa yllufssilb dna
.doof tac fo gab eht ta kcab dekool dna
.leihtureB dna retnilpS dna yllaS fO .yroR fO
,noitartsnomed fo yaw yB
egdirf-inim sih ta revo dna ,sllip fo elttob sih ta pu decnalg eH
,edoc fo enil retfa enil epyt dna tnemesab sih fo renroc kcab krad eht ni tis dluow regoR sA
.eromyna ksed sih rednu t’nsaw eciov ehT
”smelborP taC“   yojne esaelP
.ton yas dluow tsoM
gnihsilbuP xoF deruomrA yb
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,eludehcs retniw sti ot gnivom si goD fo ecioV ehT dna
,gnisiar neeb evah dluow selkcah sih taht tlef eH
saw eH .retupmoc sih ta gnittis saw regoR ,noisses llllworg-selkcah-srae na retfa ,yad enO .god-yderacS
tpecxe ylworg neeb evah dluow taorht sih dna
desiar selkcah nwo sih htiw gnidnats won saw ohw
regnif gnideelb sih dehcaer dna
.stac s’regoR tuoba deksa syawla reihsac
ksed sih rednu nwod
.egakcap sih yb dezingocer gnieb t’nerew ssalc sih ni sdohtem sih yhw tuo erugif ot gniyrt
regnif dednuow sih no dekcus eh sa deyarteb elttil a tlef regoR
.nos gnissim reh tuoba gnituohs won saw yhtanrebA .srM tub
.lufdnah a neht ,owt emaceb enO
:txen did eh tahw od ot egaruoc eht dah evah reven dluow regoR
retteb ti raeh dna yrt ot devom srae siH
.remmargorp a saw regoR
riahc sih denrut eH ”.dooF
niaga dehsurb saw gel sih
.taorht sih ni kcab gnitrats
.tnaem gnilwem taht tahw
.elttil a gnirepmihw ,ti no dekcus dna elzzum sih ni regnif sih kcuts eH
dna kcab gniog srae sih tlef regoR nehw semit esoht rof tsuJ .emit eht lla rof toN
devol siht tlef t’ndah regoR .ecin os
.yadnom yreve tuo gnimoc
.rekihhctiH flowereW
pu teg ot detrats eH
er’ew su dniheb era keeW raeB taF dna
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.esuoh ylenol sih ni ynapmoc regoR peek ot tfel saw ,tac kcalb eno sih ,hctarcS dlo ylno tsal tA
,enotS semaJ yb ”smelborP taC“
erofeb liat s’hctarcS fo hsurb a teg ebyam
,niaga tuhs seye sih depmalc
eht dna ,yrecorg eht ta reihsac eht fo eman eht wenk eH
tuoba gnihtemos gniyas dna sdnah reh gnignirw ylsuovren
,emoh morf dekrow eH
.reh ot gninetsil yllaer t’nsaw regoR .doolb
dna depley regoR .mih
swap s’regoR yb gnittis-
.gniklat ,poots s’regoR no gnidnats saw yhtanrebA .srM   .daetsni
der dewolg seye owT
ydaerla gnikrow ti denigami eh
,rekihhctiH flowereW
saw sihT      sraey ni
,no dna no tnew ehs sa rood tnorf sih ni kcarc eht hguorht kcuts daeh sih dah eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.enog saw hctarcS nehw od dluow eh tahw derednow semitemos eh
seciov dna sdrow rieht detubirtnoc ohw ecalperiF eht fo sdneirF eht lla dna
,llip sih dnuora pu ti daw dna
seye gnitnuoc deppots regoR
nehw siht tuoba gnikniht llits saw eH .regoR thguoht
,tol a truh regnif gnissim siH
.snoitartsurf emos ot timda lliw tep a sah ohw enoynA
elaT s’retsamdrowS A
rehtegotla gnikool deppots dah eH .neethgie ta
.hctarcS ta kcab dekool regoR ”.esaelP .taC .dooF .oN“
.taC“ .sdrow derepsihw
.sgel sih yb gnihsurB
,taht gniod gnieb t’ndah ti fI
— neewollaH taht woN
.goD fo tsohG s’raey siht sedulcnoc siht dna
.hctarcS gnipeels eht ta niaga decnalg regoR .gnihtemos yb-
.sgel sih tsap derednaw mrof krad s’hctarcS emit txen eht niaga nwod hcaer ot ylno draobyek eht ot wap sih denruter regoR dna
,floWcaM boR yb daeR  .tenalpruF yb
.yawa dessap stac devoleb s’regoR ,sraey eht revo eno yb enO
,reisae elttil a ti ekat ot gniog
.gniwoem dna sgel sih tsniaga gnibbur saw hctarcS dlO
.noitnetta dna doof gnidnameD
,hcaer fo tuo ksed eht rednu deraeppasid tac eht
ekil leef dluow tahT .stac wen yna teg t’ndid eH
,ylluferac ti parwnu d’eH
.yteixna sih htiw pleh ot sllip emos regoR evag eH .ylgnidnatsrednu daeh sih koohs adnik rotcod eht dna
.ksed eht rednu dekool dna
?nwod tsehc sih gnihgiew eldnub gnirrup elttil a t’nsaw ereht fi ma3 ta pu ekow eh nehw od eh dluow tahW .meht fo yna ecalper t’ndluoc eH
ees t’ndid eH .desserped mih edam ti dna
.diadnab a dedeen dna doolb hcum oot gnitsat saw eh dediced eH
.dapwap sih nwod deppird doolb krad fo elkcirt a dna rotinom sih fo wolg eht ni ti ta dekool eH
,llew ,demees ti esuaceb
dna nwod wap a hcaer dluow eh os etartnecnoc ot gniyrt saw regoR
ksed eht rednu-
.eseehc naciremA fo ecils a tuo llup dna egdirf-inim tnemesab eht ot revo klaw d’eh nehT .llip a tuo ekahs dna
.yrujni dna doolb htob snrecnoc thginot yrots ruO .denoituac eB
.flesruoy tub ti ekam nac enon rof ,deecorp ot noisiced eht ylluferac hgieW
.dluohs yeht nehw neve spahreP
,htaerb peed a koot eH
.evif emaceb seye owt ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT