.thgir lla eb ll'uoy tub" ,dias eh ",thginrevo yats ot evah uoy yas yehT"
",hguone tae t'nod uoY"
.uoy rof yb gnidnats TJ9WK"
.nur eht no stimsnart ro sedih ohw rettimsnart llams a htiw
.gnihton uoy evael dna lla ti tae ll'I ro ereh revo swap ruoy teG"
.stcejbus lacinhcet fo ecnarongi dneterp ot dekil dnuoh eht
,mih rof tuo dekrow ti rehtehw wonk ot detnaw ehs woN
".dluow uoy fi ,tnemetats lamrof a su evig ot yadnoM no eciffo ytiruces eht yb emoc ot uoy ksa tsuj ll'I
.edisni ycneuqerf rettimsnart eht htiw sepolevne delaes sniatpac maet eht evig ll'I
.yllamrof dednopser ytsuR
.yltfos detaelb enohp llec sih
.sdneirf esolc ro elpuoc a erew yeht spahrep os ,lrig eht ot dehcatta eb ot demees sevlow eht fo enO
.edis eno ot gnidnats srevresbo fo luftsif eht morf tuo gnas kcaJ nehT
.tnorf eht no 'S' neerg gib eht htiw
".yug elttil etuc A"
.esruoc fo ,dum no detnuoc t'ndah eH
.loohcs edarg ecnis rehto hcae nwonk dah owt ehT
,gnidliub eht fo kcab eht ot llaw eht dewollof eH
,sediseB" ,deunitnoc dna
,nihc sih ot pu retaw dloc ni saw eH
.egnellahc a s'tI .nuf s'tI"
.emit ruoy htiw od ot tahw rof saedi retteb on evah uoy eveileb t'nac I
.tekcop eht revo derediorbme eman tsrif sih dna
"?yawyna siht ekil yad gnirps a no edisni dekcol
.tlef reve ev'I hcuot gnirussaer tsom eht evah uoy
",dnim ni taht peek ll'I"
enil eht fo daeh eht ta dehcnup stekcit rieht gnitteg
trihstaews tew sih debbarg swap rehto nehT
.retteb hcum os neeb evah dluow rehtaew gnirps yrD
,ti dnuora nwo sih depparw ytsuR .gnorts dna
.detseretni er'uoy fi dnuora emoc ot emoclew era uoy fo ynA
",neht ,no uoy reehc ot ereht eb ll'eW"
,srae sih ylno htiw
ytiruces erom elttil a mih gnivig
enil eht morf degreme kcaJ emit eht yb aet deci dna ,dalas
.traeh nwo ym retfa lrig A
.nus thgirb morf seye sih dleihs ot fi sa pu wap a gnidloh ,dias eh
",ytsuR ,retal uoy hctac ll'eW"
".oidar ruetama ni tuo detrats dna desnecil teg uoy pleh ot yppah er'eW
...ekil sdnuos langis eht tahw fo elpmas a s'ereH"
",sraepoorD ,ydaerla yaw ym nO" .derekcins ytsuR ".gnihton
lla uoy gnipeek s'tahw oS"
.etunim yreve fo tuo sdnoces net tsael ta rof timsnart ot evah I
.epip siht nwod s'eh kniht I"
.foorpretaw si tnempiuqe oidar ruoy epoh I" .delkcuhc kcaJ
kcen sih dnuora ni gnipeerc saw retaw eht dna
ydob nwo sih gnisu yb tsuj gnidnif noitcerid  ta doog saw ohw adanaC morf xnyl a ,eoJ dna ,sniwt elgaeb eht ,ydnA dna nhoJ erew srebmem maet eerht rehto ehT
.wap rehto eht yb moor eht fo tuo reh deggard kcaJ sa mih ta sregnifwap reh delggiw asiL dna ,mih dlot kcaJ
:yojne esaelP .orevO ovitlA rednu nozamA no dna
.llew sa ytilanosrep yldneirf ,tnasaelp a dah ehs dna
,etercnoc devruc saw mih rednu ecafrus eht taht denimreted eh
.egnellahc a tnuh eht gnikam no sucof nac I yaw tahT
.enon dnuof dna dloheot fo dnik yna rof tlef eH ".xof
.ti nioj ot wap rehto sih devom ylwols neht dna
tsiaw sih ot pu retaw ni flesmih dnuof eh ,hsalps yddum a htiW
.retaw yddum eht otni nwod gnippils llits saw eh taht dezilaer eh nehT
.noitidda wen eht fo llaw eht dehcaer xof eht
"'RA USK9W ED
dnuora dekool ytsuR
,dlehdnah sih ffo denrut dna rettimsnart eht detekcop-er ytsuR
.ereht eb ll'eW" .dias kcaJ ",gniht eruS"
,ylisae mih tops d'yehT
,supmac no slrig eht htiw ralupop etiuq mih edam seye das dna srae nat ypoord s'kcaJ
.KO eb ll'uoy taht wonk ot deveiler hcum lla er'yeht dna
".em ni detseretni reh speek ti fi ti htiw gnola og ot gnilliw m'I dnA" .dettimda
,llabesab gniyalp ti denrae d'eH
.efil sih ni esu dluoc kcaJ gnihtemos eb thgim ytilibats elttil a thguoht eH
,ytsuR ta dereep kcaJ ".xof
.sduolc eht neewteb yks eulb fo sehctap erew ereht tub
.yawyna gnivael tsuj erew eW" .dias raeb eht ",esrun ,thgir lla s'tI"
.sselesu dna retaw fo lluf ydaerla ylbaborp er'yeht ,thguoht eh ,esac yna nI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.deksa ehs "?ytsuR ,egnellahc doog a su evig ot tes llA"
.ytsuR em sllac enoyreve tub ,derF m'I" ,delbmum eh ",haeY"
.airolG morf egassem a dnuof dna liam-e yna rof retupmoc potpal sih dekcehc eh
.esnopser ni gniggaw morf liat nwo sih peek etiuq t'ndluoc eh ,llitS
,airetefac eht otni yaw rieht edam yehT
",gninrom worromot htab a teg ot gniog si xof eht ekil skooL"
.deppots dah niar eht tsael ta tub yggorg tlef ytsuR ,ffo tnew mrala eht nehW
.sesserdnus rieht ni sklaw nedrag eht gnisiurc era slriG
.xof eht ta pu dekool dna
yltfos delkcarc reviecsnart sih neht tsuJ
.etercnoc tew eht revo gnidils
.nepo saw ti yhw tuo dnif ot gniyrt eb ll'ew dna ,derevoc eb ot desoppus saw tI
"?syas ti tahw sessam dehsawnu su gnillet tuoba woH"
,ereht tiaW" .yletaidemmi derewsna eoJ
.ffeJ ta deddon ytsuR ".retteb
,orevO ovitlA yb
,detacol ton llits si derF
.gniht doog a saw hcihw
.rennid retfa tfel thgilnus fo sruoh fo elpuoc a evah ot tnemom eht ta ecin demees ti tub
.deneppah tahw no troper a tuo llif ot evah I
.deddon dna seye gnilims s'flow eht otni dekool eH
.tuo ti dehguoc dna dekohc eH
.gnireenignE fo tnorf ni thgie ta teem ew ,lleW .KO"
,dloc eht htiw bmun
.ecneidua llams eht ot denrut neht
kcaJ ",gnikcart dna seitivitca roodtuo ni detseretni s'ehs ,lleW"
.skeeg gnireenigne uoY" dias ylno kcaJ
rettimsnart tnuhxof eht gnitekcop
.thgil rebma htiw wolg ot demees yehT
.ti noitnem ot ton yrt I os ti ot desu nettog ev'I ,dniM"
.retteb uoy wonk ot teg ot tnaw I esuaceb ,taert yM
.ytsuR ,uoy tog ev'I"
.dennirg ytsuR ",eruS" .wonk ot detnaw dnuoh eht
",wonk uoy os tsuJ"
.dnuora slrig eb ll'erehT
,ecaf a edam ytsuR
.gnineve eht ni neves ta
?KO ,uoy esaeler yeht sa noos sa pu uoy kcip ot worromot ereh eb ll'I
,flow gniniamer ehT
.yvarg dna ,seotatop dehsam ,faoltaem fo niatnuom a otni gud dnuoh eht sa deggurhs tsuj ytsuR ".yot
.tleb sih ot niaga ti gnippilc
.ti gnitaeper erofeb sdnoces ytnewt tiaw neht
,kaew tlef pirg siH
.mialc a gnikats m'I
.ti rof tnempiuqe nwo ruo dliub dna ngised lla eW
,erac lausu eht htiw snoitceles sih edam ytsuR
.yllausiv uoy tops yllautca ot tsrif eht saw I esuaceb now nosfloW taht detsisni ehs tub
.mih dniheb tuhs pans rood eht tel dna
tnemeticxe fo piy llirhs a draeh eH
...eerht fo tnuoc eht nO"
.noos oot tnemom a ton snoitpo sih gniredisnoc
deb eht yb riahc eht ni deyats flow llat ehT
tsirw s'ytsuR no ruf eht htiw deyot walc xedni siH
.noitautis lacitilop emos fo thguoht eh tahw
.gninrom yadrutaS kcolc'o thgie ta gnidliuB gnireenignE eht fo tnorf eht morf trats ll'eW .doog
,taht timda ot dah eh nevE
"?nori gniredlos a htiw edisni deldduh er'uoy dnA"
"?sannetna htiw uoy pihw ot gniog er'yeht yas uoY
.ytsuR etacidni ot nwod wap sih gnignirb ,decnuonna eh
.ytsuR ot yart airetefac a dednah eh sa ,kcaJ deerga
.ti no gnittis neeb d'eh erehw ti gniffulf dna gnihtooms yldednim-tnesba
.hgual ot dah ytsuR .deralced eh
”naC uoY fI eM hctaC“:yojne esaelP
.thgir saw kcaJ ebyaM
pirg ot gnihton dnif dluoc swap sih tub
.emit emas eht ta aera noitcurtsnoc yddum taht ni devirra smaet htoB" .deunitnoc eh sa
wonk reh gnittel dna snoitseggus reh rof airolG gniknaht ,rewsna kciuq a desopmoc ytsuR
.tsacerof rehtaew tsetal eht tuo kcehc ot mih degru osla dna
.rebmemer ,fo erac nekat erew uoy erus ekam ot desimorp I
.uoy fo erac ekat yeht erus ekam ll'I .uoy tog ev'I"
.snoitceliderp sih tuoba ytsuR esaet ot dekil eH
.ylteiuq mih dlot ffeJ
syarra annetna lanoitcerid dleh eerht llA
".gnidliub citelhta eht drawot ffo enog s'ytsuR taht noitacidni raelc a tog ev'I"
,otni deppils d'uoy eloh eht ot thgir tnew ehS
",emit siht tnemeerga eht saw tahT .sroodtuo dna supmac no yats ot evah I"
,gninekawaer epoh fo kraps a ,no dleh eH
.tliub gnieb saw noitidda eht erehw sedacirrab dna tnempiuqe fo elbmuj eht dehcaer eh litnu
.xof a er'uoy esruoc fO"
,sdnoces net rof stimsnart tI
.thgir tsuj neeb dah meht fo eno taht
.edils sih deppots taht
.woleb morf gnisir saw retaw eht ro gnippils eb tsum ti rehtie ,no gnitser saw waptoof sih revetahW
NAC UOY FI EM HCTAC' syas tI"
,seye sih gnisolC
.thgis fo tuo peek ot meht gnoma egdod ot elba eb thgim eh yadrutaS no dnuora llits erew yeht fi dna
.egnellahc doog a dna ,noititepmoc lanoitidart a s'tI
.gir laiceps a tliub ev'I tub
.yot xof elttil a tsuj llits er'uoy rednow oN" .delkcuhc eh
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,lortnoc citamotua eht ni dedeen eh tahw rof tcefrep neeb dah meht fo enO
renroc eno tuo emoc dluow eriw annetna ehT
sgab citsalp owt edisni delaes saw rettimsnart tnuhxof ehT
,ffeJ saw ereht dna
,ylffurg dias dna mih ta dekool raeb ehT
.elbat eht rednu swap gnidloh erew yeht niatrec tsomla saw eh
enohp llec sih hcaer ot yrt ot wap rehtie htiw llaw eht ni maes eht fo og tel erad t'ndid ytsuR
,sirbed fo selip dna dum eht hguorht yaw sih kcip ot gniunitnoC ".tsew
.dewolla gnitnecs on
.dessim uoy tahw no ni uoy llif em teL"
.kniw yls a htiw ,dedda eh ",oot syoB
.pu hsinif lap eninac sih dehctaw eh sa aet gnippis tas dna
"!woN .ylwols yrev pu em llup ,KO"
,llits wap sih gnidloh saw flow ehT
.dias eh ",revo s'ti litnu esualppa ruoy dloH"
.ffats sub eht rof reisae ti ekam ot syart eht otno sehsid eht dekcats ytsuR ,gnilkcuhC
.airolG saw os dna ,deb eht yb gnidnats erew asiL dna kcaJ
.dluoc eh sa llew sa no dleh dna desnet eh
thgis ylno esu ot dewolla era dna ,esruoc fo ,oidar yb etacinummoc nac smaeT
.wap s'ytsuR dezeeuqs dna
.desimorp ytsuR ",taht od ll'I"
.snwal eht no tuo gnihtabnus dna eebsirf gniyalp era ,etuc er'yeht dlot m'I tsael ta ro ,syug etuC
.pu ti dloh dna rettimsnart ynit eht tuo llup ot tekcop sih otni gnihcaer ,deddon ytsuR
",etatS ta ereh ngis llac bulc eht si USK9W"
".sdrawretfa hcnul rof og ew nehw reeb eht yub sresol eht dna
.kniht I ereht fo tuo uoy dellup ew retfa kcohs otni tnew uoY
,gnimit trats I nehW
.derohcna ylmrif mih dah flow gib eht tub
.ti did asiL nehw tlef dah eh taht etuc dellac gnieb ot noitcaer emas eht evah t'ndid ytsuR ,wohemoS ".etuc
.gniggaw llits liat
.mih ta nwod gninnirg ,deddon kcaJ ".ti
,sdnuos gnipruls yddum elttil htiW
.nosfloW morf maet eht enimaxe ot denrut eh nehT
?ees dna emoc ton yhW" .dehgual xof ehT
,keew tsal eht ni lla ta deniar t'ndah ti ecnis
.neht dehgual enoyrevE ".ecneirepxe
.ni dehsur retaw yddum dna
.esac ni tsuj gab piz citsalp a ni rettimsnart elttil eht tup ot dediced eH
,derewsna eh ",si ti erehT"
.mih evoba thgil eht ssorca devom wodahs a sa
.tnempoleved lausunu yrev a eb dluow taht hguoht ,renniw eht semoceb eh
,liat sih tuo koohs eH
",sdnekeew no noon erofeb pu sekaw ruf tneced oN .stsihcosam fo hcnub a er'uoY
,rae eht no ytsuR delzzun dna tneb eh nehT
.dum htiw derettaps ecaf dna srae
.taht ta worbeye na desiar dnuoh ehT ".hceT
,aet fo gum sih htiw kcab tas ytsuR ".drow
",retaw rednu ti etarepo ot gnivah etapicitna t'ndid tub ,niar doog a rof dewolla I
derewsna eh ",yrt ot dnetni I"
",won elbuort ni m'I"
.reviecsnart dlehdnah eht morf emac slangis esrom fo dnuos niht eht dna
,uoy tuoba denrecnoc erom saw enoyrevE
.wap a tuo gnidloh ,dias eh ",iH"
snwal eht morf stuohs dna rethgual raeh dluoc eH
.cinap ot ton deirt ytsuR
.gnitanicullah eb tsum eh thguoht eH
esirprus sih ot tub ylleb sih no delwarps eh dna
,ylwols gaw ot deunitnoc flow llat ehT ".nur
.elbuort eht rof yrros yllaer m'I dnA"
.trats daeh ym rof ffo ekat I neht
,llaf eht ni tnuh txen eht tsoh ot teg lliw maet gninniw ehT
.taht ekil gnihtyna ro dnuof eb ot gnitiaw dna eert a ni tuo gnignah on ,yltnatsnoc evom eht no eb ll'I
.rewes mrots taht nwod pu dedne uoy woh em llet tsuJ
.enigami tsuj nac I ?skeeg lriG" .dehgual kcaJ ".maet
.ti tuohtiw uoy dnuof evah ton thgim I
hctaw sih ta gnikool dna waptoof sih gnippat fo wohs a edam dna
,ylduol derepsihw dna
.daeh sih koohs dna dennirg ytsuR ".egnellahc
,rettimsnart eht htiw pu hctac ot setunim ytenin evah dna
.pac llabesab sih no annetna eht ot elbac niht a yb derehtet ,rettimsnart ynit eht tuo dellup eH
,nekcihc dellirg sih htiw swodniw eht yb elbat a ta detaes saw eH
,dedda eh ",xof ,retaL
.mih ta dekniw dna devaw airolG
",eoJ ,dum eht ni stnirptoof ees nac I"
.uoy htiw ereh neeb ev'I esuaceB"
.ni gnitapicitrap erew uoy emag eht tuoba wonk ydaerla I
.nosnhoJ deT reciffO"
.ti fo raelc eson dna ,seye
".setunim neetfif ni dne sruoh gnitisiv dna ,esaelp ,emit a ta srotisiv owT
"?yrrauq ruo uoy erA
.ereh TJ9WK"
.wap a pu dleh dna
.evoba morf delworg eciov railimaf ylwen a dna
.gniggaw liat ,dias eh
.ysae ti gnikam ton m'I tuB"
.tnatsiser retaw ,tsael ta rO .yllautca ,si tI"
.ereh steg dworc eht erofeb tae s'tel ,nom'C
.tuo mih pleh dna hcaer ot yrt I elihw ,mih retfa nwod pils t'nod I os tleb ym dloh uoy fo elpuoc A
.wap sih gnidloh llits saw enoemos taht dezilaer eh nehT
decniw ytsuR .gninetaerht ylniatrec erew seiks eht
,gnikrow saw ti erus ekam ot kcehc kciuq a retfa
.saw eh naht rellat dna esned erew hcihw fo tsom
.ssot nioc a yb delttes eb lliw snoitagilbo esoht neht
.yob xof a htiw pihsdneirf emit gnol sih tuoba dessarrabme eb ot evah t'ndid eh tnaem tI
retnec etaudarg eht ni
,tiftuo egalfuomac sih ni ylkciuq desserd eH
.sdaeh rieht koohs sedis htob no srebmem maet eht llA .deksa eh
.muidats llabtoof eht ot ecnartne eht etisoppo enoz noitcurtsnoc eht morf gnigreme
.llihc a etiuq dah uoY
.ssergorp sih tlah ot gnihton htiw dum yreppils ni llihnwod gnidils saw eH
,tsrif edisa yart sih dehsup ytsuR
.rood eht ni daeh reh dekop pac etihw a ni knuks A
.dias ehs ",era uoy erehT"
",esimorp I" .deddon ytsuR ".nosaer
.renniw laiciffo eht deralced m'I
.nwod tas eh sa elims ykrep a mih evag asiL
.liathsuB ,tuo gnirps s'tI
.snedrag lacinatob eht otni teg ot deb rewolf yddum a hguorht tuc neht
.spil sih gnikcil dna gninnirg
,redluohs eht otno nwes hctap eugael oidar a htiw tekcaj a erow eH
.ecafrus eht otno tuo mih gard ot depleh dna
.sdnuos gniparcs tew draeh eh neht
.od I ,seY" dias dnuoh eht ,gniddoN
.hguoht ,dluow uoy derugif I
mih dellac dah ehs taht noitatirri emos htiw ylno derebmemer dna ,ecno tsuj ylfeirb reh tem dah ytsuR
.yllaciziuq dekrep srae sih ,deksa eh
,drawpu evom ot nageb yeht
,edis eno ot htgnel s'mra ta ti gnidloh
.yart nedal ylivaeh a htiw
?KO ,gniog er'uoy erehw hctaw ,emit txen tuB" .dias eh
,yllufnruom daeh sih gnikahS ".taht
,sburhs nemiceps neewteb dettort eH
,drawkcab pets a koot xof ehT
",IZN9W" .decnuonna ehs
.hctaw sih ta dekool dna deknilb eH ".enigami
"?gnireenignE ot revo llorts ot ydaeR"
deb sih ni pu delruc eh ,gninrom eht rof tuo sehtolc sih gniyaL
.seye s'ffeJ ees dluoc ytsuR dna
.ssenkrad eht ni mih dlot eciov eht ",ffeJ s'tI"
.setunim wef a rof ecnelis ni doof eht no dekrow yehT
seenk sih ot pu dum hguorht gnidaw fo smaerd otni ffo detfird eh wohemoS
”naC uoY fI eM hctaC“
,mih ta dekniw neht
,rojam ssenisub A
.enod gniyduts hcum teg t'ndid ytsuR ".ereht
.yawyna ,saw ti depoh eH
”naC uoY fI eM hctaC“ saw sihT
.edistuo lla era slrig ehT" .deksa dnuoh eht
.edis rehto eht morf gnidliub citelhta eht dnuora emoc yltnerappa dah yehT
?yadrutaS a no kcolc'o thgiE" .denaorg kcaJ ".sannetna
si yrots s’yadot dna
.dias ehs ",yaw rieht no er'yeht ,secivres ycnegreme dellac ydaerla ev'I"
,srae dellihc s'xof eht decreip neris a fo dnuos ehT
.gnittimsnart llits ylbaborp dna
,delkcuhc eh ",wonk uoY"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sdnoces net rof yllacitamotua gnirts noitacifitnedi edoc esrom a dnes lliw tI
.ekac reyal fo ecils a nwod kcaJ gnihctaw
.tsal ta elims a dekcarc nosnhoJ reciffO ".sknahT
,retaews rettel etihw sih gniraew saw dnuoh ehT ".ereh
sroodni gnidneps neeb d'eh emit fo tnuoma eht rof pu ekam ot htob
.hctaw sih ta gnikool ,deralced rosseforp eht ",thgir llA"
".htuom gib ym dna eM
,erofeb keew eht rettimsnart tnuhxof sih tuoba ecivda emos rof reh deksa d'eH
.tsal ta wap s'xof eht gnisaeler ,pu doots ffeJ ,gninnirG ".kniht
moor sih fo tuo deppets eh
.snoitseggus lareves dereffo ehs dna
.gniod saw I tahw ot noitnetta gniyap toN
.dettimrep gnikcart tnecs oN
.wap s'xof eht fo og gnittel tuohtiw ,riahc eht ni kcab denael ffeJ ".dessim
.wap rehto sih ni ti dleh dna
,gniknilb nageb DEL der A
.yletal hcum oot moor sih ni gnidih neeb d'eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.senoz krow esoht fo tuo yats dnA
.ereh nepo oot saw ti dediced dna
.mih dnif llits thgim yehT
.airetefac eht ta rennid rof kcaJ nioj ot pu deklaw eh sa
,selur eht yb deyalp I ediced segduj eht fi dnA
.dellac eciov a ",sinaC ,hO"
.oidar dlehdnah ro
".gninrom worromot htob uoy ees ll'I
,dehcterts dna seye sih debbur ytsuR
,gnidliub citelhta eht edistuo tnemevap eht nwod yltnalahcnon deklaw xof ehT
,thgis dna tnempiuqe oidar ylno gnisu ,em etacol ot setunim 09 teg yehT"
,htuos dedaeh dna ti dnuora deppils eh ,renroc a ot tog eh nehW
.smaet tnuh gniusrup eht morf yawa
.maet nwo sih ot kcab gninrut erofeb elims a gniksir ,delbmum eh
.gninrom yb pu raelc ot detcepxe saw ti tub
.syart rieht llif ot rab dalas eht dna selbat maets eht gnoma gnivom dna
.flesmih kcamswap ot detnaw ytsuR ".uoy
flow dab ,gib a rof dnA" dias dna kcab delims tsuj eH
.yletal gniees neeb dah kcaJ mohw dnuohyerg gnikool tnagele rehtar a saw asiL
,ecnasiun a saw emit gnivas thgilyad thguoht yllareneg eH
,rezinagro dna eerefer eht si nagoL rosseforP
.yddub xof sih dettops eh nehw
,rehto eht neht dna waptoof eno htiw tlef eh ,ylsuoituaC
.hceT nosfloW ta revo morf rehtona dna etatS ta ereh bulc eht morf eno
.ylfeirb srae kcalb sih gninettalf
"?dias uoy kcolc'o thgiE
.airolG ,ereht uoy teem ll'eW"
.paeh yddum ,gnirevihs a
.nosfloW rof niatpac maet ,esuohyarG ffeJ m'I"
.riahc sih kcab gnihsup
,supmac no dna sroodtuo yats ot sah eH
,ytsuR ot dias eh
.setunim net ni ranimes scimonoceorcam a tog ev'I !spoohW"
.dedda ehs ",dum htiw derevoc er'uoy nehw etuc neve er'uoy dnA" .dekniw asiL ".erus
.yllautca ,llew ytterP"
.ecaf deirrow s'esuohyarG ffeJ otni thgir gnikool saw eh taht dnif ot
,em dnif ot gniyrt eb lliw smaet owT
",raeh ot detnaw I tahw yltcaxe s'tahT"
,yletelpmoc yawa tnew thgil ehT ".tuo
aet sih dehsinif xof ehT
.flesmih rettimsnart eht tliub eh ecnis rof gnikool er'uoy tahw ebircsed mih tel
.pu doots dna kcab riahc sih dehsup neht
maeb thgilhsalf tekcop A
.yadrutaS no ekat thgim eh shtap neddih ro secalp gnidih elbissop tuo kcehc ot dna
.ti nekat evah yam derF reverehw
,trats daeh etunim 51 a teg I
",nos ,thgir lla s'tI"
.gnidnes no thgir tpek tsuj sruoy fo rettimsnart elttil taht sinaC knahT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ytilibissop eht fo eton latnem a edam ytsuR
.ecneirepxe taht taeper ot tnaw t'nod I" .dias eh
tnuh eht rof stoob rebbur sih tuo gid ot eton a edam eH
.nac ew sa tsaf sa tuo uoy teg ll'ew dna ,no dloH
.tegrat gnivom eht eb ll'I emit sihT
saw taht gnidliub citelhta eht ot
.hctaw sih ta gnikool ,dias nagoL rosseforP ",neht KO"
.retaw eht otni gniknis dna pu gnivig
.elgna eerged 54 a tuoba ta detlit saw ecafrus ehT
,wodniw sih morf selddup wef a ees dluoc eH
.enola ssorc ot yssem oot s'tahT .uoy dniheb thgir er'ew
.maet s'nosfloW no meht fo elpuoc a era ereht raeh I ,tcaf nI
",muidats eht drawot enoz noitcurtsnoc eht ssorca tnew eh kniht I
,etis bew ecivres rehtaew eht ot gninruT
.decnuonna ehs ",TJ9WK si sihT"
.scitelhta setaicerppa ehs tub ,noisserpxe eht nodrap ll'uoy fi ,xof a ehs si ylno toN
.eb dluow rellac eht ohw gniwonk
.diarfa m'I ,tluaf yM
.stros suoirav fo smaeb lanoitcerid gnisu eb ll'yehT .sannetna pihw toN"
.delims dna ytsuR ot denrut raguoc ehT ".tnempoleved
,ogol ytisrevinu eht htiw trihstaews neerg a no gnilluP
",hguoht sneppah reven tsomla tahT
.detcartsid yldetcepxenu gnileef
,gnitnap ereht yal eH
,ecnartne eht edistuo tsuj gnitiaw saw kcaJ
.etunim a flah rof stej ruoy looc tsuJ"
"?thgir ,timil emit a s'erehT
.nirg yhtoot a mih evag kcaJ
tiftuo egalfuomac sih no detnuoc xof ehT
.ti ees ot stnaw ehs dna asiL ot ti denoitnem I tub ,taht ekil gniht ykeeg emos rof tsuj pu teg t'ndluow I ,dniM
.won dleif llabtoof eht ot epacse on eb dluow erehT
.dias ytsuR ",ees I"
",doog s'tahT" .dias eh
,niaga wap s'ytsuR dezeeuqs eH ".rebmemer
,tnemom a rof edisa skoobtxet dna seton sih gnittuP
,devirra noonretfa yadirF nehW
.thguoht eh ,noitcurtsnoc eht gnirud derevocnu tfel ,gnihtemos ro niard mrots a eb tsum tI
.noisserpxe das yldetareggaxe sih deileb taht nirg a htiw
.dennirg dna daeh sih detlit flow ehT .ksa ot dah eh
,ytiniffA ruF no dnuof eb nac tra dna seirots esohw stnelat ynam fo esroh ecnassianeR a
.smaet s'nemow rofi neve
.tuo bmilc mih tel ot
,slaudividni sa ro smaet sa krow nac yehT
.annetna maeb dleh-dnah a gniyrrac dna staews neerg gniraew ,ereht saw airolG
.oot ,etuc saw nexiv ehT
.srehsalf derewop-yrettab dna sesrohwas fo edacirrab detcere ylitsah a tsniaga pu emac eh
,eerht eht fo tsellat
.yletelpmoc retaw eht rednu gnidils morf peek ot redro ni ,desnet selcsum
.edacirrab a revo deppoh dna
.ssem taht ni mih dnif ot tcepxe t'ndluow sreusrup depoh eH
.edis rehto eht ta yrebburhs eht otni nedrag eht dessorc dna ecap sih dewols eh ,setunim wef a rof tiusrup on evah dluow eh gniwonK
,hsur sih fo etips ni dna ,mih dehctaw seninac owt ehT
.delims dna eson nwo sih dekcil kcaJ
,deraeppaer thgil ehT
.dnah yb edoc esrom ni segassem dnes ot gniyrt elihw
dum eht no yldetcepxenu deppils waptoof siH .rehtona dna
eb ot desoppus si rehtaew ehT
,swap sih htiw gnileeF
.gnirewsna eoJ draeh eh ",taht regoR"
gninrom eht ni ylrae siht gnihctaw saw eno on tub
.em retfa trats nac yeht nehw smaet owt eht llet ll'eh os
.yletaidemmi sreusrup eht fo thgis fo tuo teg ot gnidliub eht fo renroc eht gnidnuor ,tort ksirb a ta ffo koot dna
.ezag sih deciton yeht nehw mih ot deddon dna
,nwo s'ffeJ no dekcol llits erew seye sih dezilaer eh nehw dessarrabme tlef ytsuR ".tuo
.tuo gnis tsuj ,gniucser deen dna sekal eseht fo eno otni llaf uoy fI .setacifitrec gnivas efil evah maet ruo fo srebmem lla" ,dennirg eh
,dloc eht morf yldab gnirevihs saw eH
".xof ,worromot uoy ees ll'I"
",ris ,uoy knahT" "?derF
hctaw sih ta dekool xof ehT
.flesmih fo etips ni detseretni
.tnuh gniticxe na meht gnivig rof
.ylwols liat sih deggaw dna ytsuR drawot deklaw
,sduolc htiw yks fo elcric a ees dluoc eh ,pu dekool eh nehW
wap eerf sih ot dekooh VI eht fo etips ni thgir lla leef did eh taht dezilaer dna
.trats etunim neetfif a steg derF
,eb dluoc ti sa ydaer sa saw rettimsnart elttil eht derugif eH
.meht rof doog ,lleW
.yadrutaS no ees emoc ,llitS
"?ereht eb ot nalp yllautca uoY" .deknilb ytsuR
,ereht doots tnempiuqe yvaeh fo seceip lareveS
elbmur rednuht tnatsid a ta
"?esahc eht rof tes llA"
.yknik fo tros sdnuos ti ,llitS"
.eciov s'airolG draeh eh dna
.tuo meht ekam t'ndluoc ytsuR tub seciov gnirewsna erew erehT ".epip
.yawa syad fo elpuoc a ylno saw tnuh eht ecnis gniht doog a saw hcihw
.srotisiv ruo fo tifeneb eht rof ,skrow ti woh s'ereH"
.dedda nagoL rosseforP
,dnuora dekool eH
"?asiL htiw no gnitteg uoy era woh" ,deksa eh ",oS"
.sgniteerg deppiy srehto eht sa
.ti ees emoc dna ecifircas eht ekam ll'I ebyaM
,llafniar yvaeh htiw thgin yadirF rof detciderp smrotsrednuht erew ereht deciton eh
.yadsendeW no kcab rehtraf etuor dednetni sih derolpxe dah eh dehsiw eH
.niaga dlehdnah sih morf emac eciov s'airolG
.tekcaj knip a ni lrig etoyoc ,ytniad tsomla ,rellams a dna sevlow rebmit llat owt ,meht fo eerht ylno eb ot deraeppa erehT
.tsafkaerb ot ffo deirruh dna
.redluohs sih revo kcab dellac ffeJ
,tuo llac ot htuom sih denepo eH
"?noitca eht wollof ot elba eb ew lliW"
.em rof skoob eht ot kcab ,lleW"
,mraw saw wap ehT ".nac
.emag oidar mah a s'tI"
,yaw eht yb ,hcnul ta uoy ot tsaot a knard yehT
.tops ot redrah mih ekam ot sevael gnituorps ylwen eht dna
.gnivom pots t'ndid
.kcaJ ,lap sih fo eciov detcepxe eht dias ",liathsuB ,emit wohC"
.drawkcab ti otni deppets dna tnuh eht ni pu thguac saw I" .dias eh
",ovitlA" sa onimA yrruF dna ,lysaeW
.swap yddum detah eh esuaceb
.taht fo kniht d'uoy nwonk evah dluohs I tuB"
,niaga yrenihcam eht gnoma detaerter eH
,retaw dloc htiw llif rehto eht neht dna toob eno tlef eH
.pihw eht htiw eno eht eb ll'I
.edih s'dneirf sih ffo thgir ecnuob ot demees ti ecnis
,eohkcab a dniheb gnihcuorC ".tuo IZN9W
.rettimsnart eht dna derF dnif ot maet tsrif eht eb lliw renniw ehT
,hcum oot tneve s'yad txen eht gnitapicitna saw eH
.deneppah ylbaborp derugif ew tahw s'tahT" .deddon raeb ehT ".diarfa
.noisserpxe denrecnoc a htiw gnihctaw
.ward a gniht elohw eht eralced ot dediced eW
"?KO ,enoyna llet t'nod ,em tops uoy fI
,yrd erew sburhs dna seert delebal ylluferac eht gnoma shtap ehT
.oot ,mrofinu ytiruces supmac a ni raeb a saw erehT
.lennut dnuorgyalp citsalp a edisni ,thgis nialp tsomla ni neddih saw xof eht emit tahT
seye sih denepo eh dna
,slangis eht ot dekrep srae sih dah esuohyarG ffeJ
.edisa dekool eh dna
.sesoohc eh etuor evisave yna ekat nac tub
maet nosfloW eht ees ot rotcart yvaeh a fo dooh eht dnuora ylsuoituac tuo dekeep dna
.deralced eh ",emit tuoba s'tI"
,nedrag lacinatob supmac eht hguorht klaw a ekat ot dediced eH
.seirujni rof kcehc ot IRM eht ot uoy koot yeht nehw tpecxe uoy tfel t'nevah I
,deerga eh ",taerg sdnuoS"
,rood eht tuo yltfos deddap ffeJ sa seye sih esolc t'ndid tub
,rotcart eht dniheb gnidih
.tuo dna pu teg ot mih pleh t'ndluow ti os noisnetxe lluf ta ylno tub
.srebmem maet sih ot dellac esuohyarG ffeJ sa rewsna eht deilppus yletaidemmi oidar sih dna erew maet nosfloW eht erehw derednow ytsuR
.yalpsid eht ta gnikool tuohtiw derewsna dna nottub eht desserp eh
,kcoj a gnieb tuoba mih gnisaet pu nevig dah ytsuR
.dnuora ylwols gninrut neht dna reviecer eht dleihs ot
,daeh sih denrut eH
.ruoh eht ot setunim net ta
.elbuort ni s'eh dna ,thgir lla ereh ni s'eH"
,no dlehdnah sih dekcilc xof ehT "...ekil
.saw eh naht ygolonhcet scinortcele fo pot no erom neve eb ot demees airolG taht gnissarrabme ti dnuof eh semit tA
.liava on ot tub dlohwap a rof yllacitnarf delbbarcs dna
,em dnuof sah eno on dna tuo snur emit eht fI .seY"
.deksa eh "?xof ,ydaer uoy erA"
".ssim ,uoy morf tnemetats a deen I"
,ytsuR morf ssorca tas kcaJ
,tsew rehtraf gnivom ,llaw eht dewollof eH
.tsew eht ot kool uoy fi srehcaelb eht ees nac uoY .dleif citelhta eht rof daeH .ereh MFH8K"
,hctaw nwo sih ta decnalg ytsuR "!eerhT ...owT ...enO
.niaga gnittimsnart erofeb sdnoces ytnewt rof stser neht
ro daer eh koob tsal eht tuoba mih ksa t'ndluow asiL tnaem kcaJ taht wenk eH .dehgual ytsuR ".traeh
.stnih on dna teiuq peek tsuJ"
.thgirf a su evag yllaer uoy" ,mih dlot airolG ",ytsuR ,hO"
.waptoof a htiw dneirf sih gnikop
dna tuo snur emit eht fI
.yduts ot moor sih ot kcab dedaeh dna aera debrutsid eht dnuora deruoted eh sa
.xof eht m'I dna ,gninrom yadrutaS rof deludehcs tnuh rettimsnart a evah eW"
,mih ta nwod delims dna
.retaw eht fo tuo flah dna ni flah ,ylleb sih no gniyl saw eH
.rood eht rof gnidaeh dna yart sih gnivael
.niadsid kcom ni elzzum sih delknirw dnuoh ehT ".taht
.derewsna xof eht
.evoba morf krab gniohce na draeh eh nehw gnipmarc erew swap sih dna
.nur doog a uoy evig ot yrt ll'I
",xof ,thgir lla er'uoY"
",nigeb nac ew ,noitnetta s'enoyreve evah dluoc I fI"
,llew sa enod saw kcaJ yllaniF
,deksa kcaJ "?edih ot og uoy nac raf woH"
".edis rehto eht no si dna ti dnuora tnew eh teb ll'I
.erus rof lairetam hguot fo edam er'uoY
a saw depoh eh tahw ni hteet sih dewohs eH ".pihw
.ti tuoba em dlot airolG tub ,ereht t'nsaw I
.rettimsnart eht no nottub a desserp neht dna
.drow a yas t'now eW" .deddon kcaJ
neht gnidliub eht fo spets eht otno pu gnarps
.sannetna lanoitcerid rieht htiw em retfa og smaet tnuh eht neht dna
.yltfos dias flow eht ",kcab emocleW"
.wodniw sih rettalps ot nageb spordniar yvaeh retfa neve ,niaga dna niaga sradar rehtaew eht gnikcehc tpek dna
.ecno ta uoy fo ynam oot dna ,ysion ooT" .meht dlot ehs ",thgir llA"
,tneb smra sih peek ot dah eH
,ylsseldne serocs strops ssucsid dluoc tub ,sgniht hcus ni tseretni on dah dnuoh ehT
.kniht I ,taht ekil d'I"
,etercnoc yreppils eht no pirg yna teg ot deliaf seenk siH
.gninrom yb dne dluow ti depoh eH
,detrons ytsuR ",sufood ,oN"
.niar eht morf noitcetorp artxe emos evig dluow gab eht dna
.gnikrow neeb d'eh hcihw no tnempiuqe fo eceip ynit eht revo gnidneb emit hcum oot retfa denaorg eH
ll'I dna ,gninrom siht rof tegrat ruo si ereh derF"
wollip eht no kcab dial eH ".tlef
"?puorg eht ni smah edoc-non ynA"
.esnopser s'airolG saw
.ecno ti nees ylno ev'I" .dedda ytsuR
htnom hcae fo syadseuT htruof dna dnoces eht no gnidliub siht ni ereh steem bulc oidar eht ,yaw eht yB '.noissimsnart fo dne' snaem 'RA' eht dna
noitidda eht rof senil retaw ro sniard pu knil ot redro ni yrassecen neeb dah gniggid emos fi sa dekool tI
,despale evah setunim neetfif eht ecnO
.ssensuoicsnoc s'ytsuR fo tuo dna ni detfird eciov s'airolG "?truh eh sI"
.noitcerid rehto eht morf noitacol sih drawot gninnur
dnoces tsal eht ta emarfrood eht dnuora kcab elzzum sih dekop flow ehT
.yadot dessim uoy eno eht rof pu ekam ot hcnul evah ot gniog er'eW
,orevO ovitlA ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
,tleb sih morf ti gnippilcnU
.ylediw gninnirg ,decnuonna eh
enoemos etacol ot krow smaet esuaceb 'tnuh xof' a ti llac eW
.yramrifni supmac eht ni deb a ni saw eh pu ekow ytsuR nehW ".uoy
tleb sih morf dlehdnah retemitnec 07 nwo sih deppilcnu eH ".niaga
.etal eb ot tnaw t'ndid eh tub ,mih rof lausunu
?uoy sdnif maet rehtien fi tahw tuB" ,yllufthguoht dias kcaJ
",reeb eht yub sresol eht dna ,tneve txen eht stsoh maet gninniw eht taht em dlot uoY"
.ti htiw enog dah eh dna
,enohporcim eht otni taht ekil gnihtemos ro sekoj dab ffo selttar
.yaw eht no selddup lareves dnuora ruoted ot dah yeht tub ,klaw etunim evif a ylno saw tI .dednopser kcaJ
,mih dlot dnuoh eht ",emit tuoba s'tI"
.tsal siht htiw kool detniop a xof eht evag eH ".snwal
.noitisop sih peek tsael ta mih pleh dluoc taht gnihtyna rof gnikool
.dias eh ",yllis ,oN"
,kcaJ ta tuo eugnot sih kcuts ytsuR ".ti
dna dlehdnah a sesu tsuj xof eht yllausU
",og s'tel ,eruS" .deksa eh
"?ereht uoy t'nerew yhW" .deknilb ytsuR ".ti
"?uoy hctac yeht nehw uoy htiw od yeht lliw tahw dnA"
.niar eht ot denetsil dna
.nosaer doog a rof sedacirrab eht pu tup yehT
.gniht eht otni tif t'ndluoc eh demussa yeht esuaceb mih tsap thgir gniklaw tpek sretnuH
,seye sih ni deralf
.neht tsuj dedne egassem dnoces net eht dna
.nirg retsinis ylbatius
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.regnuh morf yawa detniaf evah d'I dna regnol hcum toN"
.esruoc fo ,ytsuR ot nwonk lla erew etatS morf maet ehT
.thgirb llits tub ,yks eht nwod gnippils saw nus ehT
.aera noitcurtsnoc eht otni kcab deppils eh os
.suoivbo syawla gnitae yhtlaeh rof ecnereferp sih
,wap s'ffeJ koot ytsuR
,gnihtemos no thguac eot enO
.tnirps a trats ot gniraperp rennur a fo esop eht gnikat ,deddon eH
.airetefac eht ot klaw eht pu dedaeh dna mrod eht fo renroc eht dednuor eh ,ecap sih gninekciuQ  ".etunim
",revelC" .delkcuhc eH
,ti otni dias eh ",tsuR derF"
.elddup tseraen eht ta wap a gnivaw
tsuj tuoba kniht ot gnitrats saw ytsuR tub
.tsirw sih dnuora ylmrif desolc wap A
.elims a htiw derewsna xof eht ",tcejorp bulc oidaR"
yrenihcam eht neewteb deppils eh sa
.ti teg dluow yug ssenisub erem a esoppus t'nod I"
snedrag eht edistuo tsuJ
",reciffO ,tnedicca diputs a tsuj saw tI" .dehgis ytsuR ".nepo
.tca na lla saw noitatirri eht taht ,hguoht ,liat yriw s'kcaJ fo gniggaw eht morf wenk ytsuR
.etuc denrad er'uoy keeg oidar a rof"
.tsaot dna sgge sih dah eh ecno elbat rieht ot mih devaw dna airetefac eht ni erew asiL dna kcaJ
,selur eht fo noitanalpxe feirb a eb ll'erehT
.ruf eht revo ylthgil eugnot sih gnissap
.tem ew nehw em ta dekool uoy yaw eht was I
.no gniog detcepxenu gnihtemos dnif yeht sselnu worromot ereh morf desaeler eb dluohs uoY
supmac no bulc oidar mah eht derosnops dna ngised dna gnireenigne cinortcele thguat ohw raguoc delzzirg a ,nagoL rosseforP
.ti fo duorp yletanidroni spahrep saw dna
.tnemom eht ta shtap ydahs eht hguorht gnillorts eno on saw ereht tub ,nedrag eht edistuo
.lautum saw tseretni eht ,uoy erussa I
.oot ,rehtaew eht kcehc ot desimorp eH
.dnuoh eht dlot  eh
.derF etacol ot langis oidar eht dna
.yks eht ta tuo reep ot wodniw eht ot revo deddap dna
,gnidliub airetefac eht drawot denrut eh sA
.xof diputS" .flesmih dlot eh
"?ffuts lacinhcet ni detseretni si asiL oS"
.gnittes lanoitutitsni dirroh eht dna
.rood eht drawot airolG derutseg eH ".yawyna
.taht llet nac eson a htiw enoynA .yllis eb t'noD
,yldeirruh eta eH ".nur ot tes lla"
'morf' rof noitaiverbba esrom a si 'ED' ehT"
dloh suounet a mih evag taht tros emos fo maes a dnuof swap sih nehw
,rehtona neht dna
orevO ovitlA yb
.doog si airolG dneirf ruoY
.ecaf gnikool das yllauteprep sih yb demrofrep nehw erutseg suourgnocni rehtar a ,dekniw dnuoh ehT ".em
.ybraen ssergorp ni
.dekcils dum dna htooms
".tuo gnitteg pleh dedeen eh ,tuo denrut ti sA
,skoob eht gnikcarc erofeB
.mih dnuora desolc ssenkrad sa
.eye nworb eno gnitniuqs
.deddon xof eht ,dneirf sih rof nepo rood eht gnidloH ".foorpretaw
.seot sih rednu tnasaelp tlef spihc doow ytsud eht dna
,deunitnoc laedro eht gnol woh erus t'nsaw eH
.lortnoc citamotua rednu slangis esrom detaludom oidua sdnes ti dna ,sttawillim derdnuh a si rewop rettimsnart ehT"