xob ybraen a no nwod puc neetnac sih tes goD eht
niap gnilgnit ot ssenkrad ni ekowa ssoV - - -
.elah ssel ro erom tsal gnol ta gnileef
,gnidleiynu ,dilos gnihtemos htiW  !dnilb
edis sti otni dellor ylerem tI
ruf dna elcsum fo klub mraw a
,etihw fo epahs gnolbo na saw mlap sih nopU
,draoba llits sdneirf dna setam werc sih htiw
,evitcepsortni eht dleh reven dah yeht
,tahw ,tuo erew uoY“
.eguh os ylraen ton tub tac nodolims a fo esoht ekil
”?sniatnuom eseht nI   ?ereh
retniw-dim fo hctulc digirf eht tsniaga doog elttil did ti tub
.ssendekan sih rof neve
,deifillom ylthgils ylno
,yltnamada daeh sih koohs dna
.llec leuf dna enigne eht fo sniur eht morf gnituog emalf
,rae s’tibbar a saw tI
,meht morf dedaf dah nrub eht tub ylgniyonna delgnit sregnif siH
denrettap ettesor saw liat dna kcab sih erehW
deddon ylpmis nybrehC eht taht oT
tsif sih desolc eH
.tniop taht retfa sgniraeb sih gnitteg on saw erehT
,egral eno tuo gnihcaeR ”.seimene ton
.tnorf s’tsaeb eht nwod dna pu ecnalg rehtona ekat tub pleh ton dluoc ezag ’ssoV
,sdnah htob ni ylluferac puc eht hctulc ot dah eH
gnidnal suortsasid a yb thguorw segnahc citsard eht etipseD
.tekcaj thgilf s’enoemos fo sderhs deidoolb dna derrahc ylthgils
.kcab mih dellup secrof gniniartser htob sa
,esolc gnitfihS
,htob meht ssorca nward neeb dah yab bmob eht morf teknalb gnitalusni egral a taht derevocsid eh
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.sdap kcalb morf krats gnidnats swalc elap
;dezingocer eh sgniht emoS
ylthgils ti gnitliT
.yaw eninac a ni elam saw goD eht
,wons peed pih eht hguorht degdurt yldeggod eH
.sthguoht peed fo noisserpmi eht evag ,ssoV ot ,taht noisserpxe na htiw
,smron namuh naht reworran saw hcamots ehT
elzzum kciht ,gnol a htiw ecaf eht ni ekil-god yrev
ffo gniraehs erofeb ecrof gnilttar hteet htiw tfarcria eritne eht koohs tI
ylleb dna tsaerb sih otni gnisruoc htmraw gnihserfer tnes diuqil toh ,hcir ehT
tnemom a depag ssoV
,ylbareffusni ,niagA
.secruoser eht eraps dluow yeht taht detbuod eh
.yrotirret ymene revo enalped ot decrof erew yeht esac ni tsuj
.egassap sih fo worruf denruhc eht ni gniggard senil sti
.snybrehC eht fo eno ;goD A
,nips talf a otni tnew ylloF s’yrolG eht ,demooD
,nam oidar dna rotagivan eht dellik taht tih kalf a yb deggarf neeb lla dah tnempiuqe MCE dna ,radar lla ,oidar riehT
gninrub erew sdnah sih yhw revocsid ot gniyrt ,tib a dehtirw eH
;tsehc sih ssorca tniartser eht yletaidemmI
,flesmih gnidulcnI
.lufecaep neeb reven dah snoitaler ,raw eht erofeb neve
raef citsivata eht
snrettap fo yteirav ediw
,dekool eh emit tsal eht ecnis dessap dah flah a dna yad a ylnO
delknirw ylwols gnieb liof-nit fo tnecsinimer ,sdnuos enillatsyrc ,teiuq edam ti taht
,yab eht fo dne drawrof eht ssorca gnuh prat a tsap gnikael
,ekaw ot elba neeb dah goD eht taht yldnuos os tpels eh daH
.debmilc ylwols ssoV hcihw pu egdir
redluohs sih woleb tsuj
,pmil eht saw smra sti ni deldarc dna
.yromem rof degnol a
,sregnif sih gnilggaw
…nrob erew uoy ,yakO“
.esirprus ni depag ssoV
taorht sih raelc ot dekcah dna dehguoc eH
.gnithgis dna elfir a gniredluohs
- - - .erom ecno mih revo elots
.gniliaf morf psarg gnikahs ,kaew sih peek ot tsuj
.slairetam evitan ylerup ,demussa ssoV
.eerf elggurts naht
ssoV gnivael ,wons eht ni yal xiS
elggurts ot deunitnoc eh nehW
,dloc saw enalp dekcerw eht fo edisni ehT
.naM yb dleh esoht dna
stcejbus yrruf htiw
ssoV tub ,nosaer elos eht eb yllaer ton dluoc tahT
.yldas daeh sti koohs dna ,gnikcab srae
.labrev sa llew sa lausiv saw
;kool egnarts a mih evag ti dna
?ruf ekil leef ti did yhw …ruF
,stnemom wef a retfa derettum ssoV ”.sknahT“
ygrahtel gnimraw A  .niap gnilgnit
,sgnidnuorrus sih ni ekat ot ylthgils daeh sih gninruT
”?ssem siht ni skeew owt ereh tuo evivrus uoy did lleh eht woH“
,peed taht ot esolc gnimoc neve fo epoh on dah ssoV
.xob ybraen eht no nwod puc eht tes dna
yponac eht fo egde eht morf deppir saw eh erofeb tsuJ
,enola saw ssoV dna sniatnuom dehctulc-retniw eht ni kcerw a saw yrolG ehT
sreksihw htiw etelper
.ydob eritne sih desuffus taht
,htiw deraperp neeb gnivah rof doog ylgnisirprus detsat ti dna
egalesuf eht morf sretem ytriht saw eH
– sih morf yawa htgnel ’smra naht ssel elttil a gnipeeK .suoiruc
;llew sa seueuq noitacinummoc lausiv dah osla snamuh ,neht tuB
…yllacipyt ,ysatnaF hgiH dna
,detcartorp a fo seorht eht ni lamina tsol a ekil gnineek niht
.pu sbmuht namuh yrev a
negnafthcaN yb eriF esaeC   :yojne esaelP
,lworg eht detaeper ti erats diputs ’ssoV tA
.tcetorp ton did romra
nur gnibmob eht gnirud degamad senigne eht fo eno litnu
,raef emaceb esirprus retal tnemom a tub
hgih os neeb reven dah srebmun riehT
!ylevitamriffa deddon ti esirprus sih ot hcuM
demimotnap tsaeb eht
ecnatsid trohs a esproc eht deirrac tsaeb eht
,rae sti revo puc ot pu tup ti rehto ehT
.ti daer ot tsirw sih detlit ssoV
;enog erew yeht nehT
,secrof ymene evoba hgih gniylf ,namria na sA
.neeb ecno dah selosnoc noitagivan dna snoitacinummoc eht erehw eloh gnipag eht hguorht gniraor dniw yci
,redluohs ’ssoV nopu yltneg psarg sih tes nybrehC eht dnah deppit walc
tsehc sih revo mra eno gnissorC
,drawnwod eht detaeper nybrehC eht
.desaeced ylraelc yrev erew meht fo llA
.tsetta dluoc reidlos yrtnafni denedrah yna sa
;ekops ssoV ,don a gnidrazaH
.semalf lonahtem elbisivni htiw
.krad eht ni tsehc sih ssorca desserp
.taob ydaetsnu na ekil edis ot edis delggaw dna ,tuo talf dleh ,desuap dnah ehT
.ylloF s’yrolG eht fo stnemom lahtel
,deppis eh sa derats ylpmis ssoV
.thgilf nruter eht gnirud gniw eht fo tser eht dniheb nellaf dna
;nirg citsilamina gninethgirf rehtona htiw mih gnirovaf ,dnuos gnillor a
nihtiw desuoh nocaeb ycnegreme ehT
?thguoht lanoitar
,yal goD eht kcab sih tA
thgil esuffid htiw erofeb naht detanimulli erom elttil a tsuj
,tfarcria nekcirts sih sa gnihctaw
srevoc yvaeh eht htaeneb morf pu gnikans dnah derruf elap a
spil reppu sti htaeneb morF
;dellems yeht sa tsuj dekool taht
.gnihgual yllautca saw eh
.eof sih morf seye sih gnikat reven
.seiceps dinac citsemod ro dliw yna no dnuof ton
’sfohk‘ egnarts taht gnitaeper retfA
eloh detsiwt ,gnipag eht morf degreme erugif a nehw
”.eniM ymenE ,ereht olleH
.egairrac thgirpu sti troppus ot kciht ylbatcepser llits tub
,snamuh fo serutcurts lacov eht dekcal sgoD ehT  .’sfohk‘ ekil
,mra derruf elap s’goD eht
.dnoyeb yellav eht otni raeppasid dna
,elttil a dexaler mra gniniartser taht fo htgnerts eht tnemom a llits saw eh retfA  .yawa
.tsehc s’tsaeb eht tsniaga kcab mih dellup dna denethgit
,tnemom a retfa ,dna deleviws dna dehctiwt srae htoB
,niks sih ta deppin etib yci on tuB
.wons fo tfird peed a ni
,tsehc sih ssorca dnab dilos
”!!?ma I sa ereh tuo deppart sa tsuj er’uoy nehT“
,krowrepap tuo gnillif sruoh ynam tneps dah eh erehw ,potksed a nO
kcab htgnerts sih tog eh litnu tub ,wonk ton did eh ,sdne tahw oT
mraw ylgnilfits tsomla saw ria ehT
.lipup krad eht dnuora tsuj gnir esnetni erom a htiw
ssoV tcatnoc fo htmraw eht dna ,dehtaerb – eh
”?em dnatsrednu uoy naC“
niatnuom eht nwod yaw sih deggols eH .ssoV rof tub
noisolpxe on tub tcapmi fo hsarc gnidnirg eht draeh yltnatsid eH
erom gnihton wenk ssoV
,thgit etuhcarap epacse sih dehcnic dah ssoV
gninruter saw noitalucric esuaceb denrub seitimertxe siH
puc neetnac rehtona otni stnetnoc s’top eht fo erom ruop ot evots pmac eht ot denruter ti ylhtooms gnisiR
seenk sti fo kcab eht woleb tsuj nwod gnignah
,sgel sih ssorca gnillaf thgiew yvaeh a
hcuot ot hguone esolc demees dnuos fo secruos htoB
.meht detrawht ohw yna
,dnoyeb dna puc sih revo dnah sih gnivom
.yrolG eht fo edisni eht yfitnedi ylisae dluoc eh
;noitsuahxe htiw dezalg ro
,ecnats ladepib sti etipsed
erom revo flesti daerps ylbaroxeni taht eripme namuH eht fo thgim eht tsniaga evivrus ot lliw suoicanet a htiw slaminA
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,negnafthcaN yb
saw ti tsaper hcir a hguoht
,ezorf eh tnemom a roF
noisiv sih ni ylizarc gnimmiws dlrow eht
ylteiuq dessih evots pmac llams a
ssenkaew peed-enob eht htiw
.lluks sih ni tuoba delttar sthguoht dekcinap sih elihw
;egdir taht dnoyeb saw yrolG ehT
yerg elap dna etihw
,namuh ton erew yehT
,staes rieht ot depparts llits erew nemwerc owt eht fo sniamer ehT
;ydoolb dna degavas esab eht
ta yllatnemirepxe gnilbbin
egdir eht fo tserc ehT
sdneirf sih ot htaed thguorb kcul lli fI
.eson nwo sti pat ot
gnidnal tfos yldesselb a otni nwod delarips eh sa dniw eht fo liaw eht tub thguan neht dna
ssenkaew sih yb detaefed ,depmuls eH
srevoc evisnapxe eht htaeneb morf tuo pils ot ton gniyrT
pitregnif a htiw elpmet sih dehcuot eh
.hguone esolc tub ,yltcaxe ereh ton ,yakO“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
?nihtiw tsol llits enob dna hself fo egakcerw delgnam rehtona ereht saw rO
,seirutnec eerht tsomla rof
.rof detnuoccanu rehto eno dna
,elbatirahc saw eno fi ,dednuos tI
,ereht llits saw kcab sih ta ecneserp dilos ,mraw ehT
,negnafthcaN yb ”eriF esaeC“
.elzzum sti gnola kcab gnilgna sreksihw sti dna
pu edis thgir yltsom tser ot emoc ylsuolucarim dah tI
.fo tnegoc ton saw ssoV
,retniw fo thgieh eht ni tuB
,revewoh ,stnenopmoc lausiv dekcal taht
.daeh sih gnikahs
,gniborp ,trela saw ti
.htiw sraey eerht tsal eht devres dah eh tnemilpmoc werc eht tsniaga daed fo wor eht deillat eh
doots ti erehw deppots ylerem tI
elap saw ruf stI
dehcnelc hcamots sih dna
.yletelpmoc ,dekan saw eH
dnah a tuo tsurht eh ylsuoutepmI
– ti sa kcab sih tsniaga tsehc s’goD eht fo gnitfihs wols eht yb dellul ,yllautnevE  .dexaler dna
tcilfnoc a yb rehtegot thguorb elpoep fo noitcelloc etarapsid eht
noisiv sih ssorca demmals kcalb sa tsuj dna ,yarg otni
.mih kcurts noitazilaer taht nehw ediw gniog seye
?snamuh ton dna ,noihsaf a retfa ,sgoD erew yeht esuaceb tsuJ
top eht gnippit ylluferaC
.sgel sih ssorca detser gnihtoN  .ssel hcum sa
.ecneserp rieht leef ton dluoc eh tub
mih dereffo nybrehC eht nehw desirprus saw ssoV
.tius thgilf dna mrofinu sih naht erom elttil gniraew stnemele eht tsniaga deraperp lli yleros saw eH
,hgis a htiw seye sih dellor neht dna
taht hguorht weiv eht gnikoolrevo
ymene lufraef a saw ti taht tcaf eht etipsed dna
sgnaf gnikool suoregnad owt esoht sediseb hteet sti fo erom delaever taht
.yllacihportsatac deliaf
ni evig tsuj ot reisae ti dnuof eh
.detcepxe ssoV sa ti ta gnippal naht rehtar
.gniddon daeh yrotaderp
delaever saw ruf s’goD eht
.eson dinac kcalb dna
.dezilaer eh ,erehw og oT
,sepat gniniart dna segami morf dellacer ssoV
,tub hsarc eht devivrus dah noitces liat eht fi rebmemer ton dluoc eH
.sniatnuom nyhsrepS eht fo sthgieh eht ni
.meht neewteb ecnatsid retem ytriht eht ssorca dereep dna
.sraey eerht rof htiw dewerc dah ssoV mohw fo htob
naht erom gnihton
.tib a yawa detfihs eh dna gnilfits tsomla
.htorb gnillems hcir
.dnuob erew yeht fi sa tlef won hcihw seot sih dah ti sa
,drawpu pit gniw eht dehctaw dah
.yaw elbategev a ni tnasaelpnu lla ta ton dna ,hserf
edisniatnuom eht no devom gnihtoN
,werc tsol reh dna ,enalp eht revocer ot deirt neve yeht fi elcarim a eb dluow tI
,pu tas eh sa nwod dils teknalb ehT
etihw ylraen yrev saw taht euh elap a eb ot
esuffid dna mid ;thgil saw erehT
.hsarc eht gnirud eerf deppir slenap ssecca roiretxe
.gniriw dna ,noitalusni
,elgna drawnwod a demimotnap tsaeb eht dnah eerf sti gnisiaR ”?deneppah tahW“
,kcohs ni deliocer eH .taem ekil
.ebab a sa kaew flesmih gnidnif tub eerf eltserw ot gniyrt ,cinap a ni dehtirw neht
ecarbme gninosirp eht ot
.lla ta digirf ton dna trofmoc fo level eht woleb tsuj ylno tub
ekahs elgnis a retfa dnah sih gnisaeleR
ro raeg gnidnal delgnam a ekil roiretxe s’tfarcria eht morf raeg dna tnempiuqe
hteet fo hsalf a htiW
,tumag eht nar seiceps eht fo sgnikram ehT
,semoc rehto eht ro edis eno litnU“
.sgnidnuorrus sih fo epahs lareneg eht tuo kcip ot hguone tub
delbmur nybrehC eht
.larips htaed reh nageb yrolG eht erofeb setunim wef a
.puos sih ni gnitaolf sgniht neerg eht fo eno
puc dereffo eht ot yawa ezag sih gnilluP
.ssenerawa taerht sih ni ecnedifnoc yna ssoV evig ton did noitazilaer ehT
,step sa tpek snamuH seninac citsemod ot derapmoc
hctaw sih erow llits eh taht gnicitoN
.mih woleb os ro teef dnasuoht emos llits
ylelituf ti ta deppals eh dna
,puos eht ta deppis osla tI
.pu ti gnirb ot evom on edam tsaeb eht tub edis sti ta gnuls saw elfir gnol A
,sredluohs ot daeh morf ruf fo ffur ehT
,niaga tauqs ot kcab gnimoC
.deniartser gnieb fo cinap gnisir eht llits ron
htolc etuhcarap gniniartser eht fo eerf flesmih deltserw ssoV naom deifirret a htiW
lrans gnikool egnarts a otni werd elzzum s’nybrehC ehT ”?tsop gninetsil A“
.sregnif sih htiw ti leef ot elbanu
.nwod evots eht no laid eht gninrut erofeb
,dliw dna hcir saw puc eht morf pu gnitfaw maets eht fo llems ehT
dnah ot dnah ot nwod emac ti nehW
,retsilb nug sih fo hctah foor eht dehctalnu
noisneherpmocni ’ssoV gnidnatsrednU
”.tsaeb yriah taerg uoy ,oot uoy kcuF“
.sniarb dna selissim dna snug htiw ,detnarg ,slaminA
tsal eht fo ecneloiv eht ot tnematset
.ssoV ot ti reffo ot esolc yrev gnittauqs
.ti psarg ot tuo gnihcaer erofeb
;mih tsniaga esolc desserp
.mih no nwod dehsarc
.ssel ylthgils ylbaborp saw ti ssam llarevo ni tub
,esirprus ni ezorf eH
.sgnaf neerg ekil tsurht seert enipla fo serips niht eht hcihw hguorht etihw sseldne tsuj
,daeh sih dniheb noitaborppa delbmur gnihtemoS
.saw ti detcepsus
,rebmob ylloF s’yrolG etal eht fo rennug lanips ,ssoV laroproC
,retal stnemom wef a mih hguorht elots
.esle gnihtemos delbmur nybrehC eht
htaeneb htrae nezorf eht ni deruocs eguog a gnivael
mraw ylbatrofmoc emoceb dah
deredduhs dna flesmih dnuora mra eno degguh neht
.fo segami nees dah ssoV taht drapoel wons a fo sgnikram eht ekil hcum yrev
.taht revo etuhcarap sih htiw
,dellacer noitacude detimil ’ssoV sa
.aesuan deifirroh ni
.yrotirret nybrehC ni llits ro sniatnuom eht fo edis deilla eht no saw eh fi
.yaw rehtie tuoba gnihton od dluoc eh
ssoV naht rellat hcum ton doots ti
.don a htiw gnihtemos delbmur nybrehC eht dna
,gnidaf stniartser eht tsniaga selggurts sih
tnemom a rof ti ta derats tsaeb eht dna
.erusopxe nwo sih dnim ton did ti
.ti no gnittis saw taht top eht rits ot evots pmac eht revo tneb nybrehC eht
noitcaer sih gnidaer fi sA
thgin elbamohtafnu eht naht repeed ssenkrad a sa
,ydob sih dnuora htrae ot ylefas mih thguorb dah taht
”.evivrus ot woh wonk uoy os ,sniatnuom eht ni desiaR
.dloc ylbaresim dna
eerf deppans ekarb bmuht eht yllaniF
dnah eno gnidnetxe
egdir eht fo tserc eht ffo morac
,dedderhs eht htiw depparw neeb dah hcihw teef sih rof evas ,dekan saw eH
.detaerc ti eloh eht hguorht tuo sniarb s’erutaerc roop eht dehcnup taht tellub eht morf ylekil tsom
.noisserpxe laicaf dna egaugnal ydob
hteet dah nybrehC
,sniatnuom eht hguorht ylsuoituac dedaerht dah nidlE niatpaC
,niaga dnuora emac eh nehw ereht llits saw goD ehT
,revo kcab deklaw dna
,dehctaw ssoV sA .werc eht fo eno
puc neetnac a otni stnetnoc eht fo emos deruop ti
snosaer rof nybrehC fo sgoD eht gniyortsed no tneb ,raw fo enihcam tsav a ni sgoC
htgnel sti gnola deppuc
.woleb yellav eht otni dereep ssoV
.mih no gnisolc yltfiws goD eht deips eh
.rennam enilef tsomla na ni detairts dna
elttil a gnikahs sdnah sih dnif ot desirprus ,tuo dehcaer ssoV
,egamad eht yb edutitla rewol a ta ylf ot decroF
,ereh fo tuo ti ekih ew ro
,enam s’noil a ekil tsomla
.evid peets a ni enalp a gnitartsulli fi sa
saera ekirts ylpmis dluow taht rotaderp trams a tsniaga elttil tnaem romra ydob sretrauq esolc nI
noyar fo tlob drawkwa eht degguh eh sa ylballortnocnu derevihs eH
”?ton did nosirrag ruoy tuB
;krad eht ni ,dekan saw eH
.etihw yleritne saw hcamots sih dna
,semit fo elpuoc a htrof dna kcab dekcor eh
puos sih dehsinif eH  ”?sey ,evivrus eW
denrut nybrehC eht nehW
.esolc ylgninethgirf mih gnidloh
.deneppah tahw wonk reve dluow eno oN
,emoh fo sthguohT
.tner gnitatsaved
,ylhtraenu na htiw desrepsretni llef dna esor naom ydaets a erehwemoS
.drah ni tes retniw
stib krad rellams osla tub
moc.yrruFoS no
etteuohlis s’erugif dionamuh dalc-etihw eht nehw ,yruf neht dna
,mih erofeb enecs elbissopmi eht gnipacse rovivrus a gniees saw eh taht gnikniht tsrif ta
,htorb dna selbategev yltsom saw tI
,rennug lanips sa noitisop sih ni ,ssoV
.sredluohs erauqs
.gniwohs hself fo knip elap eht htiw
.selcsum sih fo xepa eht ta
.ssensuoicsnoc sih ot hguorht detalocrep yllanif niarb deggof sih ,etibtsorF
.wardhtiw ton did ti tub
.gniog llits saw raw eht elihw
,niht eht otni dereep eh
.goD eht saw oot os dna dekan saw eh
.noos emit yna nwod gniwols fo noitacidni elttil yrev
,efil fo etsaw elituf siht fo trap a ton erew ohw ereht kcab sdneirf eht lla dna ,stnerap sih
.nwod eno ekat ot stluassa bom ot troser ot dah snamuH
thgirpu ylluF .ydob sti ot noitroporp ni llits tub
.ecalp ni mih gninnip dna gnihctac sgel s’goD eht fo eno
,kciht eht ta deporg eh sa gniyzzid noitom yreve edam ehcadaeh gnittilps A
,smmoc on ,seilppus oN“
?retniw ni sniatnuom eht no taem teg goD eht dluow lleh eht erehW !taeM
,prahs saw rovalf stI
.neht ,uoy dna em s’ti …oS“
.sregnif bmun morf wons dna htrae denruhc eht otni ti pord yletaidemmi neht oT
gnitanimile ylpmis ro gnitagujbus ,tenalp eht fo erom dna
eripmE rieht ni secruoser dah yehT
dlrow eht tnes cinap siH
,revewoh ,ssam rewol taht etipsed gnorts ylbidercni erew yehT
.niwt tsol sti rof gninruom ni fi sa gnimaercs enibrut gniniamer reh
;saw eh erehw aedi on dah eH
.mih no sucof rieht nip ot denrut ruf elap fo srae ralugnairt ,llat eht elihw
.ediskcab sti morf drawtuo ylthgils dleh gnieb etipsed
?wonk uoy od ,neht ,ew era erehW“
,os flah ylno saw tsehc sti
,taerg s’tsaeb eht
.ydaerla deipucco yeht sdnal hcir eht dna
;llew sa deggurhs tI
.debmilc semalf egakcerw detsiwt sti morf dna epols eht nwod yaw flah
tnemom taht ta dezilaer eh dna mra reppu sih tsniaga dehsurb esle gnihtemoS
.mih niartser ot evom ton did goD ehT
,latem fo stib detsiwt ylsuoedih
derevocsid ssoV dnA
deffuhc nybrehC eht
.woleb teef dnasuoht elpuoc a
– ?rotpaC  ?reucseR  ?tahw
,trapa emac ti raor gninefaed a htiW
.dniw eht fo sgnaf yci gnikeirhs eht otni tuo debmilc dna
.dellacer ssoV ,erofeb ereht neeb ton dah tahT
,sgel deyalps htiw ,ytimixorp hcus tA
.retlehs fo eerged emos eb llits dluow ereht
.retsloh sih ta ylsseltiurf deknay dna
.tcapmi eht yb flah ni tuc gnieb morf enalp eht tpek taht enola kcul saw tI
.sevlesmeht yb ot yrotciv gnirb ot detcepxe ron detrats ton dah yeht
.thgie derebmun werc rebmob eht
.ygnirts ylthgils saw ti hguoht
etuhc gniyolped sih fo knay gnihcrul eht retfA
”!?syad neetxiS  ?syad …neetxiS“
.evitisop a dnoces eht dna
.gnippis ylwols ,deksa eh ”?woH“
,elibommi dna etum dennuts
egar htiw dehcnip rehtien saw mih dedrager taht ezag ehT
.peets ton saw epols eht
,gnol dna kciht ylgnisirprus saw liat ekil-god ,yhsub stI
ffo deraehs dah gniw gniniamer reH
.desopxe saw hself sih ;derevoc ton saw mra sih taht
seirotirret nybrehC neewteb sniatnuom eht ni erehwemos tsol saw eH
.ypsar eciov sih dna yrd taorht sih ,derettum eH ”.ssoV“
.eucser a tnuom ot meht rof yrotirret namuH ot hguone esolc dehsarc dah eh ebyaM
tnempiuqe radar eht tuohtiW
edistuo wons eht ni deyarra smrof delgnam
.detanimretxe eb ot slamina suht
.dias yeht tahw etalsnart ot smargorp retupmoc detacilpmoc esu ot dah snamuh yhw saw tahT
tuoba detfihs ssoV
.ssalg niht fo tuo edam neeb yllautca dah liof taht fi
delgnit regnol on seot dna sregnif siH
.did tsaeb siht drager suoiruc
.nybrehC eht fo oediv ro shpargotohp nees ylno dah ssoV
.eerged emos ot dah ti taht detcepsus eh
.eussit ekil gniw dna gnisuoh hguorht gnicils senibrut deeps hgih eht
.deppis eb ot niaga pu nekat saw puc eht sa
deirrac werc lla lotsip ecivres eht rof ti rednu gniggid
,egaugnal nybrehC eht fo hcuM
.worruf eht fo htgnel eht nwerts egakcerw fo seceip dna stib eht rof tub etagivan ot reisae saw taht
.riah trohs sih gnilffir ria fo tfaw mraw a
- - - .niaga rebmuls otni deppils
ediw naht repeed shgiht htiw
repeed dna rekciht saw tsehc eht tub
niaga dnah sih gnisiaR
,snoinapmoc elttab sih
.goD eht fo ecneserp mraw eht gnitsiser deppots tub ,derettum ssoV
nonnac eson retemillim ytrof eht dnuof eH
.tsetnoc on netfo tsom saw ti eno no enO
esnetni os dloc rettib a yb dezieS
?devivrus dna ,neht ,tuo erew uoY“
a ot senot dexim ot sroloc esab citamorhconom morf
,esruoc gnirettulf
.wons eht hguorht dedaw eh sa flesmih tuoba ylthgit smra sih dehctulc
demussa ssoV os gnihtolc fo kcal sti dnim ot mees ton did tsaeb ehT
esolc desserp mih dniheb ecafrus eht
teknalb gnitalusni eht fo thgiew eht htaeneb seenk dna sdnah otno pu dellor ti
.niaga don dna ,doN
,yrros xis esoht ot dehsalf sthguoht siH
.won ,thguan saw taht fo lla tuB
.ti htaeneb morf tuo delwarc dna
.ylevitamriffa debbob daeh sih dna
smra htob gnisiaR  .don rehtonA
tniop a ot nwod gnicart erusserp yratnemom a ylno
.nwo sih fo hgis a htiw
- gel sti gnikcik
mra reppu sih hguorht decnal niap fo kcirp A
thgilyad fo ruoh emos saw emussa ylno dluoc ssoV tahw fo thgil mid eht nI
.ksed eht ot denruter dna esor eh sa erutseg gnimlac a ni nwod dna pu gniwap dna desiar dnah eno
enalp daed a ni deirub
.sregnif sih gninepo dna
kcab hsup ot deirt eh sa snosirapmoc esoht ekam ot stnemom wef a koot ssoV
,daorb mih gnivig
tsehc sih ssorca gnidnib eht fo ecnatsiser eht tub
ydob eritne sih hguorht
.gninworf ,hgis a htiw desuorg nam ehT
.detaba hcum saw ehcadaeh sih niaga ekowa eh nehW
.daeh laitsaeb eguh taht fo ekahs a neht ,don A
;etarucca neeb dah noitazilaer reilrae sih taht
?mih gnikaw tuohtiw nruter dna ,doof eraperp
,noitasnes dnoyeb bmun teef sih
ekarb bmuht eht netsafnu ton dluoc
.srehto evif edisgnola nwod ti dial
eht fo tserc eht revo deraeppasid dah taht rebmob demood eht epacse ot eno ylno eht neeb dah eh fi derednow eH
.nybrehC eht dehctaw eh sa pis latnemirepxe na koot dna ti ta welb eH
,evitagen a tsrif eht oT
,diulf krad elap eht ni tuoba detaolf sgniht neerG
.dnuora lla depsar dna derettiks ssih gnitarrusus A  .htaed gnizinoga
,elbazingocernu ylrettu saw ti fo hcuM
.dnah eno ni puos sti dleh nybrehC eht
.goD eht gnicaf saw eh litnu denrut dna
,ylevisulcxe ,llew
skcarrab sih fo retlehs dna htmraw eht
.esolc yletamitni
.gurhs dna daeh sih ekahs saw
”.dekcuf htob er’ew ,neht lleW“
!tsaf mih dleh taht mih dniheb tfos ylreeuq tey mraw
,mrala ni yawa nael ot ssoV gnisuac
.gninrub sdnah dna teef sih htiw
saw esoht fo tseraen ehT
,dellac neeb reve dah yeht sa ,erew yehT
.taorht kciht sti fo shtped eht morf lworg gnihguoc a ekil tuo emac taht gnihtemos delbmur nybrehC ehT
.skcar egarots dna staes morf gniddap degnuorcs fo paeh a no gniyl saw eh taht dezilaer eh dna
saw reyal elbuod eht rednu htmraw ehT
”eriF esaeC“ saw sihT
ylfeirb kcab gninnip srae llat ,dehgis dna
emit eht ta gniod saw eh tahw gniredisnoc ylsuoicsnoc tuohtiW
.gnitartnecnoc fi sa desolc ylthgils seye htiw daeh sti gniwob
,atsap fo etalp a ekil ssam detsiwt a ni
meht ot elbaliava dah yeht secruoser eht htiw deifsitas etiuq
,yab werc tfa eht ni saw eH
,taem fo tibdit llams a no
,dootsrednu yletaidemmi ssoV taht noitom a
.detaeper eH ”.ssoV“
”?snamuh ta gnitoohS  ?gnitnuh
enalp dekcerw sih fo roiretni eht sa tnemom eht rof ti derongi eh tub
,gninrub tub gnihton leef dluoc sregnif gniwaht sih tub
,ylgnilttesnu os etiuq ton saw kcab sih ta ecneserp mraw eht dna
,dna dlihc a saw ssoV ecnis seirotirret s’goD eht revo gnilttab neeb dah nybrehC dna snamuH
settesor yarg-eulb eltbus htiw delttom tub
.taem dna stnalp fo tneloder
.mih hctaw ot woble eno no pu flesti depporp dna
,did llits ylbaborp tI
ylevitalpmetnoc delbbin ssoV
detlit daeh taerg s’nybrehC ehT
.tcapmi eht devivrus ti ecnis
,pu ti hctans ot deirt dna tuo deirc eH
;sgel sih fo kcab eht ot ssa ot sredluohs morf ruf leef dluoc eH
seirotirret nybrehC eht otni peed eitros tsal rieht gnirud tih ytsan wef a dereffus dah yrolG ehT
”?uoy fo erom era erehT“
,dednecsed sgnaf gnol ylgnissertsid owt
.deddon nybrehC eht hgis gnol a htiW
deddon ylpmis goD eht
ffuh a tuo tel tsuj eh oS
.egalesuf eht fo deniamer tahw morf gnimoc ekoms yna ees ton dluoc ssoV
.htorb toh eht ta deppis ylsuoituac eh sa deksa ssoV
.neht ylno ymene eht fo ecneserp eht ot tcaer did ,revewoh ,ssoV
,flesmih dnuora depparw etuhcarap eht ta dewalc ylitsah eH
;namuh a fo esproc derrahc ylegavas
.regnif eno tsuj neht dna semit eerht ti denepo dna
.xob eht fo egde eht revo
dniw eht fo naom eht rof tub tnelis saw dlrow ehT
ylloF s’yrolG eht fo esproc eht ot del
,oga ytinrete na ekil demees tI
,retnec eht ta etihw ot sedis htob morf gnidaf stops eht
.tsop s’rennug tsiaw a fo
ro yawa mra s’goD eht gniyrp morf
;werc sih reh htiw dna
snoitacinummoc yaw-owt fo noitnevni eht htiw yllacitamard degnahc dah noitacinummoc lacov riehT
,dewehc eh sa ylgniyfsitas dehcnurc tI
,dnuorg gniniag rehtien htiw
,yltpurba tsol tcatnoc oidaR“
.elcric flah a ni ylevisnapxe mra sih devaw neht
;erom ecno sgel sih revo llef thgiew a
.tnempiuqe scinoiva fo eceip a dleh ecno dah taht
seert dna wons fo eerf detsalb neeb dah hcihw hsarc eht fo dleif sirbed eht deretne eh litnu
depurdauq yna ekil deleeh-hgih dna rednels erew sgel gnoL
,enola thgis yb ylf ot decrof neeb dah yrolG eht
.strop nug liat dna tsiaw eht morf gniruop semalf was eh
,gniliec eht drawot detniop eh
,sregnif daerps sti pu dleh ti
,revewoh ,mraw saw mih dniheb ecneserp ehT
. wons ssorca gniwolb wons fo surrusus eht dna
,tcatnoc yratnemom s’enalp demood eht yb desopxe tfel kcor dekan fo eguog eht hguorht egdir eht gnitserC
eh ytilibommi ot tsomla debmun sregnif htiw ,tuB
”?deirub tog tsop gninetsil ruoY  ?ehcnalavA“
.eripme namuH eht yb derised yrotirret larenim hcir ezies ot stpmetta eht detsiser ylno yeht
.tius thgilf sih gnitaemrep ssentew yci dna hguorht dekaos stoob sih
.erusopxe ot eud htaed tfiws yrev a morf mih devas dah gniht nmad eht taht ezilaer ot emoc dah eH
.waht ot gninnigeb saw taht hself nezorf yllaitrap ot
ecreif erom reve gnimoceb sedis htob neewteb selttab eht htiw
.ecrof tcapmi eht yb detavitca
,niaga dettauqs dna retal tnemom a kcab emac eH
.kcab sih tsniaga esolc desserp saw ecruos taeh elibommi ,dilos a dna
.retniw enipla eht ni tsol
.swalc elbatcepser yrev dna
.erafraw fo sedaced owt tsomla rof mih otni dellird drah neeb dah taht
teknalb etihw emosrebmuc a ekil flesmih dnuora etuhcarap sih depparw dah eH
.pis rehtona retfa dedrazah eH ”…gninetsiL“
.klat meht gniees yllautca tuohtiw dneherpmoc ton dluoc snamuh taht sreyal ynam tfel llits taht tub
.niarb debmun-eci sih hguorht detalocrep
.sdneirf neeb dah yehT
nwohs dah ti dnA
.redneg tnerappa oot lla s’tsaeb eht saw sA
,derebmemer osla eh ,tuB
si yrots s’yadoT dna
dnah eno gnisiaR  .noitarepsaxe
”?deirub teg tsop gninetsil ruoy did oga gnol woH“
.seiretra detcirtsnoc eci hguorht desruoc doolb fo hsur neddus eht sa
.ecalp ni ezorf dna ,yletaidemmi ssoV deips ti
;ni dednal eh yellav eht ni elbisiv segalliv on erew erehT
ksed eht ot revo yaw sih gnikciP
.smrofinu rieht fo sderhs eht dna sepahs delgnam lareneg rieht dnoyeb namuh sa deifitnedi eb neve dluoc weF
- mih demrofni dnim ’ssoV fo noitrop tnatsid a gel sih
.eerf lotsip eht deknay eh dna
nees reve dah ssoV segami eht fo lla ni tuB
sdnoces suoicerp esoht ni yrolG eht nodnaba ot deganam esle enoemos daH
sdnal namuH otni dnapxe ot detpmetta yeht dah roN
egalfuomac etihw retniw fo mrofinu thgil a ni dalc saw tI
.meht dniheb yawa gnilbmut dna
don evitamriffa na niagA
.puos sih ni wef ecracs erew ereht
,cinap gniworg htiw elbmuf ylno dluoc dna
dloc yb bmun deredner neeb ton dah taht dnim sih fo kcab eht nI
niap eht tabmoc ot gnihton did noitazilaer tahT
tsrif eson pots a ot dils dah yrolG eht gniredisnoc
,sgel sih gnissorc dna thgirpu flesmih gnittis
.taorht sih ssorca regnif elgnis a gnikar erofeb
,erac detcepxenu htiw ,dna
.ssendiccalf decudni elttab ro erutrot htiw kcals ro egar htiw delknirw rehtie erew yehT
”?retsasid rehto ro gnibmob morf daed s’enoyreve erugif yehT
,raw eht detrats ton dah nybrehC eht
,eguh saw pota daeh eht dna kcen sti fo sruotnoc eht delaecnoc
”?eucser a detnuom yeht t’nevah yhw nehT“
noitcerid rehtie ni tub ,evoba thgieh ralimis a
.ekohc ro dnapxe ot dah yeht taht
ysatnaF ecneicS fo retirw remrof a si ohw
.detnaw nwo sih taht
.aimrehtopyh htiw suoicsnocnu gnol woh swonk dog retfa
,ria eht ni nrut ot deganam eh
.slworg detsehc peed rieht morf sdrow mrof ot erutalucsum eht evah ton did spil niht rieht dna
.yab yrennug dna yab mmoc-van devar eht neewteb
wons detullop dna seert deniur fo lennahc A
od dluoc eh lla os elbmur ytaorht
,mih dniheb detfihs gnihtemoS
.semalf eldnac ekil tuo dekniw
eulb tselap eht erew seye s’retsnom ehT
dnab gnidleiynu ,mrif a tub
.noitartsurf fo erutseg lasrevinu a
decartuo noitcaer erehw
,nwod dekool nybrehC ehT
”?nybrehC ro ,yrotirret namuH
;sedalb elkcunk dna sevink dah snamuH
,kcurts ti tnemom eht gnittimsnart nugeb evah dluow