,gnilims em ees uoY
.no evoM .ma’am ,ereh ees ot gnihtoN .gnihtoN raef I
:ylisae tser ,hteet ym wohs I fi tuB
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daeR
.raen yrev ma I taht
,sselehtenon meoP
.gninnirg ro gnicamirg m’I
,”taC erihsehC“   yojne esaelP
,nway sgnihton rediw ,segdeh ediw htaeneB .enog lla
.hcus yna dna uoy dilos no
.sretsnom ,stsohg ,sralgrub
,goD fo ecioV ehT eht no
yrteop dna seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
erongi t’nac uoY
,gnilims em ees uoY
.hcuot ot ereht ton si tahw dnuow tonnac uoY
.ereh ton ma I tub
.doow ytpme na si siht
,gnilims em ees uoY
ekoms ekiL :esuap on em evig snrecnoc lairetaM
.ereh ton ma I tub
.doog ro lli rof ,em nosaer ro emyhr t’naC ;llet t’nac uoY
,em eb yam ti rO .yleuqsetorG
,nelarD yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
:sgniht elpmis raef ew nerdlihc sA
,rebmemer ot llew si ti tuB .snaol tneduts
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sseltxetnoc si htrim yM
.doom laitnatsbusni ym fo drow tsrif ehT lleps tonnac uoY
.ereh ton ma I tub
nus thgiliwt eht eb yam espmilg uoy tnilg ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.llaw eht ni gnirrits era sehcaorkcoc ehT .daehrevo gnilbmub era shtomeheb ehT
.llaf ot raf oot raf dedaf ev’I .em ekaT
,ytilatrom lanosrep
;lla ti edave dluow dna ,esnes emos ev’uoy fI
hctulc yeht nehw sregnif hguorht edils I
em ees t’nod uoy fI
,dluohs uoy sa od t’nac uoy erehw ,dlrow siht nI
seirots s’nerdlihc fo tselpmis eht neve gninnigeb yrev eht ni taht
emussa tseb nehT
,taolg oT ,swalc ruoy neewteb ylbignatni krims oT
:daed ti llac I
:detacilpmoc erom worg sraef ruo ,stluda sA
,yrtogib nairatirohtua gnisir
.em naht gnihton erom s’gnihton dnA
,gnilims em ees uoY
,flowcaM boR yb meop a evah ew thginoT dna
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
floWcaM boR yb meop a
nur sdniw dliw eht erehw ,denoitroporpnu llA
.noituac ekat ,ssecnirP
.raelc og ot si edih ot yaw tselpmis ehT
.egap yrrufos sih no
.ereh ton ma I tub
nwal eht no ro ,seert wodahs eht neewteB
.raeh ot ereht ton si tahw
”taC erihsehC“ saw sihT
.xofnogarD reppaD eht
.nekopsnu tnew taht daerd laitnetsixe eht lla dna ,doohdlihc morf rebmemer yam uoy retcarahc gnisuma na tuoba meop a ,tniop ni esaC .doolb tuoba saw
.ytrap a ti llac yehT
.ereh ton ma I tub
,dias ecno egas deton a sa
.lwarc sroloc gniwalc eht ,sruos cisum ehT
?raeppasid dna nirg tub od uoy nac tahW
.hcum oot enog eb tonnac eno ,em eveileB