.ecnedifnoc sih dedore gnillewd eht fo ezis elbissopmi eht
.deppots skraps dna gniltsihw eht nehw detnioppasid ylevitisop dekool tI
.metsys norevA yna ot egassap efas uoy teg ot yrt lliw I“  .dehceercs ti
.noisseccus kciuq ni enrobria erew xis llA
dnuos gniltsihw llirhs sti gnihsaelnu
derutseg otkiN niagA ”.klat uoY“
.efil sih rof deggeb utaalK sa tnaig eht raeh ylno dluoc liatkcalB
?ygolonhcet tceted ot liaf tub
.noitcerid yna ni ytilibisiv tcefrep rof dewolla llehs raelc stI
.eye eht ni hcae dekool eH
.tnaig eht detrela evah dluow enola esion ehT
”.desived reve snopaew detacitsihpos tsom eht htiw deppiuqe era eW“
”.ris ,spihs gnitceted m’I“ ”.no ydaetS“
.erutaerc gnikool ecin a ton saw ti ,dniheb dna evoba morf deweiV
.stsermra sih deppirg liatkcalB
?meht htiw raw ta eb osla stnaig eht dluoC
,sgnirps elbixelf no slewej depahs-rats niwt sti htiw eceipdaeh s’adaraB sa gnikirts sa ton saw tI
,dopsnart a ni era uoy nehW
.dop sih fo edis eht tih wap a sa nips dlrow eht was eH
.daeh sih koohs liatkcalB
deknay liatkcalB
dnim sih no ylivaeh dehgiew
enil a ni tsrif eht fo llehs eht dettap eH
,adaraB dna otkiN“
dil kciht a htiw xob leets a denepo eH ”.uoy rof tpecxE“
,yb dekcit sdnoces eht sA
”?serutaerc eseht tuoba em llet uoy nac tahW .otkiN“
.erew yeht sa llat sa saw rednilyc hcaE
.ezirp siht rof thgif ot deraperp saw eh tub
.yawllah eht nwod
.stnaig htiw detsefni si tenalp ehT
”?segaugnal elpitluM“
.tnaig eht drawot mia trepxe htiw ti dellor dna
teef s’retsnom eht ta dop reh dereets adaraB
”.dellik flesmih teg ot gniog si toidi ehT“
”?spahrep ,snorevA
resolc tog yeht sA
.tnaig eht rof gnikool
dewoc t’nsi llits ti fI
.krow siht ekam ot mih ot pu saw tI
.kool ot daeh sti denrut kraz ehT ”!ifiF“
demees egac a ni ymene na gnipeek fo thguoht ehT
,hteet detniop htiw deniL
yawllah eht fo dne eht ot meht del eH
.keehc sti tsniaga reh debbur dna
.bmob noitcudni rorret a si ,ris tahT“
esion gnicreip-rae na sekam tI
gnivaeh saw tsehc s’adaraB
.moor eht dnuora decnalg liatkcalB
”?ytinasni ot derutrot neeb ti saH .wonk t’nod I“
,hguone esolc saw eh nehW  .yawa dekcab dna
.gnihton was eh dalg mih edam
”?snoitseuq rehto yna ereht erA
.sgnidliub tnemtrapa esir hgih fo ezis eht
adaraB detfil yltneg tnaig ehT
”?tsrif ycamolpid yrt ew t’ndluoC“
mees troper s’eborp eht fo sesimorp dliw eht edam noitategev hsul ehT
.revird eht gnirit tuohtiw sllih peets bmilc ot ti wolla taht sthgiew dezirotom sah tI
”.srotaderp eb dluoc yehT“
.derepsihw adaraB
.nottub hcnual s’elissim hcae deppals dna
ria eht hguorht gniylf mih tnes tih wol A
.stnadnep rotalsnart dna sgnirrae rotacinummoc tuo dessap otkiN .od dluow ti tub
”.ereh pu sdop eht teg s’teL
.drawrof deppets dna werc eht ot denoitom eh
.sbonk wef a denrut ehS
.yltrop deredisnoc saw koz 001 sih dna llat deredisnoc saw erutats cim xis siH
.mih ot kcab sti htiw
.renosirp norevA na gnidloh si tnaig ehT“
.teef reh dnuora ylevitcudes delruc liat yhsub reH
.yawsserpxe enal ruof a eb ot
,dnah eht yb utaalK gniggarD
.reh ot deddon tub ,elamef eht fo dnof oot gnieb rof flesmih dedihc eH
sriats ot del taht htap enots a dnuof eh
.nrut ni eno hcae dekool eh
”.egac eht ni kcaB“
”?rood siht sesu kniht uoy od tahW“
.deremmats utaalK
,gninetraehsid saw tcaf ehT
.yawa deihs werc eht fo tser eht sa sretsinac eht fo eno pu dekcip adaraB
.yawllah eht llif llits tsum taht
”.ti htiw no teg s’teL .snoitseuq hguonE
.ecafrus eht drawot yltnelis dils elttuhs eht sa tnelis erew yehT
”?meht hsup ot deraperp ew era raf woH“
”.ris ,pihs norevA na si ti kniht t’nod I“
.norevA na saw egac eht edisnI
.nur ti tel uoy sa gnol sa noitalsnart enifer lliw margorp ehT
.hturt eht wonk ot dah eh tub
.tod ynit a llits saw tenalp eht tub
”,segaugnal evif ytxis ni klat ybab kaeps nac tI“
.dop sih fo ssalg kciht eht hguorht elbidua ylerab saw utaalK  ”?ereh ,norevA nA“ .tuo delwarc dna dopsnart reh fo hctah eht deppop adaraB ”.ti eerf tsum eW
skrab prahs fo seires a delruh kraz ehT
.dop sih fo mottob eht ta llab a otni delruc yal otkiN
.derepsihw eh ”?stnaig eht tuoba su llet uoy nac tahW“
.efil sih gnivig si eH“
”?os yas uoy t’ndid yhW
gel s’tnaig eht tsniaga decnuob kraz ehT
.noitisop sih deifingis retnec eht ni relleporp llams a htiw paclluks depirts der dna neerg elpmis siH
.mrofinu yratilim tsenif ruoy ni desserd uoy fo hcae tnaw I“
.skcot 05 nihtiw noisiced sih ekam ot evah dluow eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,hcinniM dieR yb
nihc sih rednu tennob s’niatpac wolley dna knip sih fo nobbir dlog eht gniyt erofeb htab tsud detnecs a ni degludni eh
.moor s’norevA eht otni denepo hcihw llaw eht degguh yehT
.tnaig eht drawot dehcaer otkiN tub
,snoisolpxe neewteB
dop sih otni debmilc eH
.noitamrofni elbaulav mih evig thgim ti
…sevals gnilliw htiw
”.edis rehto eht no teem ll’eW
.rood tnerapsnart eht desolc eh tnemom eht ssel delbmert otkiN
.moor eht dennacs eH
.erutaerc tnegilletni na ton saw siht ,ylraelC
.rebmemwerc gniniamer ylno sih ot denrut dna
.kcot a rof werc eht dna mih egaruocne taht tel dna
.xob eht otni dekool ehs sa denediw seye s’adaraB
.dekaeuqs otkiN ”?ris ,dehsiniF“
.hsinif reven lliw tI“  ”.dehsiniF
.dopsnart sih ni aera gnidloh eht otni snopaew eht dedaol eH
hctah sih denepo eH
.snug gib eht esu ot evah t’now ew ,yllufepoH
.redrah neht ,tsrif ta ylthgil egac eht no deppat liatkcalB
”?egaugnal rieht etalsnart uoy naC
.nees reve dah liatkcalB erutaerc tsegnarts eht saw tI
.kcab nrut tonnac eW“
.teprac tfos a yb denoihsuc yltnelis dellor
.mih no gnippets eciton dluow tnaig a hcus detbuod eH
.bmob noitcudni rorret eht esu ew ,ycrem rof gniggeb ton si erutaerc eht fI
.uoy eerf lliw eW“
.tnaig eht fo smaercs eht rof denetsil eh
.hguorht lwarc ot hguone ylerab mottob eht ta denepo saw wodniw ehT
”kcattA allihcnihC“ saw sihT
.epahs ralugnatcer egral a htiw dellif neercs ehT
,koz dnasuoht net fo thgiew eht dnatshtiw ot dengised era sllehs esehT
.moor raf eht otni deraeppasid dna denrut tI ”.god daB“
”.ecnetnes emas eht ni aedi doog dna eman sih esu t’nac uoY
evom t’ndid drib ehT
,selbat htiw moor suonrevac a ot ecnartne eht ta dedne teprac eht erehw
.wolla dluow skeehc ybbuhc sih sa hcum sa denedrah ecaf s’liatkcalB
.srab eht tsniaga stsif sih taeb eh litnu
.secaf rieht no noisufnoc eht ees dluoc eH
.tuo deirc otkiN ”,tiaW“ – si woleb tenalp ehT
.redneB ycatS ,efiw sih htiw ifics yrruf dna yrruf
.wodniw eht rednu llaw eht fo esab eht ta dopsnart eht tfel eH
.reciffo retupmoc sih fo noitcerid eht ni deralg eH
,gnidliub eht fo edis txen eht dnuora yaw sih gnikaM
.delley otkiN ”,yrgnuH“
ezalba sevren sih tes noissucnoc dna hsalf tsrif eht ,os nevE
.dehctaw dna dop sih fo slortnoc eht depirg liatkcalB
.yawllah eht nwod degrahc kraz eht sa edanerg hcnets a werht dna
.yawllah eht fo dne eht ta deraeppa tI
yawa nrut t’ndluoc liatkcalB  ”?… eht … uoy erA“
.esion eht fo tsrow eht morf mih detcetorp dopsnart eht lufetarg saw eH
serutcurts latem esraps htiw aera na detceles ydaerla ev’I“
tnemmoc s’utaalK ”.dessimsiD
,llew meht did dna sksat rieht wenk werc siH
?ygolonhcet rieht si hgih woH“
.yllufepoh dias eh
sriats eht fo pot eht ta otkiN was eh nehw reisae dehtaerb eH
.snottub wef a desserp liatkcalB ”.sselepoh saw tI
eb tsum serutaerc eht ,rood dna reddal taht fo ezis eht yb gnigduJ“
.srehto eht ot llaw eht nwod derepmacs eH
tnaig eht revo emac kool delzzup A
.tnemom eht yb desaercni gnirevihs s’utaalK
,od ot esle tahw erus toN
nopaew siht fo esu eht dessentiw eh emit rehto ylno ehT
.teef sih ta gnirewoc saw ti nehw tnaig eht ot yas dluow eh tahw desraeher dna seye sih desolc eH
.yranoitats eb ot raeppa lla tub tibro ni senihcam egral lareves era erehT“
.gnidrocer sih deunitnoc dna
.sekaw ralletsretni on era erehT“
.won noitseuq eht saw thgif a fo hcum woH
.liatkcalB niatpaC si sihT“
.yaw eht del dna
.dnah a desiar yldimit utaalK
.esolc denael ohw
.adaraB ot denrut dna htaerb wols a tuo tel eH
.ecaf sti fo tnorf ni dnah sti devaw dna dehguoc tI  .deffins dna
.revo saw ti nehT
tegrat sti tih tI
?su dettops yeht evaH ?spihs norevA yeht erA“
.serutaerc egral owt ro eno ylno gniniatnoc hcae
.tsrif reh dehcaer dna gninnur emac kraz eht tub
reh htiw egac eht ta pu derats eH
.ymene ruoy ta retsinac eht llor dna nottub eht hsup uoY
meht ta thgir dekool kraz ehT
moor rehtona ot gniklaw deunitnoc tnaig ehT  ”.dnuora teelf eht nrut ot evah eW
noitisop sti niatniam ot delggurts dop ehT
,enoc htgnel-rae derekcehc etihw dna kcalb s’otkiN sa llat sa ron
.leurc ylbaveilebnu
,detadimitni ylisae era yeht fI
.selissim arodnaP fo xob eritne eht detfeh liatkcalB
.srae sih neewteb deretnec saw ti taht rorrim eht ni gnikcehc dna
.skcot evif ni traped lliw eW
.yllaidroc meht deteerg eh ”,olleH“
.revo koot gniniart yratilim s’liatkcalB
.tnaig eht fo pets wols hcae htiw koohs dna dekaerc gnidliub esnemmi eht fo roolf ehT
.thgir og lliw I dna utaalK
.tenalp ruo no noitavrats ecaf ro
.sdnah dna ecaf sti tub ydob sti fo cim yreve revo htolc deroloc ylthgirb erow tI
pu dehcaer tnaig eht sa
.deprihc rotalsnart sih
.serehps tnerapsnart fo
,sdnoces eht tnuoc ot deirt niarb sih fo trap emoS
.llems dab yrev a sah dna
”?nur dna dnuora nrut ew llahS“
.egac yhtlif a ni desolc seye sti htiw
”?esruoc tpecretni na no era ynam woH
.thgit seye sih desolc dna srae sih derevoc liatkcalB
”,od uoy sa hcum sa ecneloiv etah I“
”kcattA allihcnihC“
deralf elttuhs eht sa egrus lanif eht tlef eH
.dop sih fo ytefas eht ot elop eht nwod kcab deirruh liatkcalB
,otkiN dna adaraB rof gnitiaw elbatrofmocnu werg yeht nehW
yawa raf erehwemos morF
llah eht fo dne eht ta moor eht ni detaes saw tnaig ehT
.egnih pot sti morf ylisae gnuws tI
.dedolpxe eh ”?tahW“ ”?riS“ – I
.flesruoy ot netsiL“ .dedaelp ehs
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.seY“ .dekrab eh ”?tluciffid os noitasrevnoc yreve ekam uoy od yhW“
”.stnaig eht no letni tnatropmi evah yam tI“
,detaefed dna detsuahxe dnuorg eht ot deppord bmob ehT
.ssalg eht tsniaga tib hteet ehT
.sgel dna smra sih ezorf rorret tub
.yllacitonpyh denoorc ti ”,tfos os era uoY“
.deremmats otkiN ”?sdrow wef a denrael ylno sah tI .ris ,gnihtoN“
”?klat ybab denrael ylno ti dna
.werc sih fo secaf denethgirf eht ta dekool liatkcalB
.derepmihw otkiN
.tnaig eht fo rae ynit eht otni egassem sih detaeper dna
.yllamron klaw si od ot evah uoy llA
”?selissiM arodnaP esoht t’nerA“
,teef sti ta rednilyc gnissih eht ta kool ot desuap tI
egac eht fo pot eht no nwod flesmih gnirewoL
”?stnaig eht tuoba su llet uoy nac tahW
.emit eht dekcehc eH .hctarcs a tuohtiw kcatta eht derehtaew dop siH
.eci ot doolb sih denrut taht
.rotaderp a eb dluow seiceps neila txen eht elbissop syawla saw tI
.pot no nottub der a htiw retsinac neerg krad a pu dleh eH
,tnedifnoc dnuos ot deirt liatkcalB
.dehcaorppa tnaig eht sa yawa dekcab eH ”?… eroM“
dewols yltneidebo kraz ehT
.mih ot kcab sti denrut norevA ehT
,efil tnalp dna ,ria ,retaw tceted eborp a dluoc woH
.tnialpmoc s’reenigne sih fo drow tsrif eht decnelis ecnalg gninraw siH
”?uoy htiw gnorw si tahW“
,reh rof dehcaer ti sa hctah eht denepo dna
.slortnoc enigne eht evoba derevoh ti sa derevihs wap s’utaalK ”.koz dnasuoht evif hgiew dna llat cim 09
,detaelb otkiN
”.pu tuhs ot em dlot uoY .ris ,deirt I“
sag suoixon fo duolc eht otni deklaw tI
,etacinummoc dluoc yeht taht woN
.noitadipert htiw dias ehs
nur ot detnaw eH
?yrgnuh era uoY ?yrgnuH“
.gnidaelp sih fo erawanu ylgnimees
.emit eht ta dekool liatkcalB
”.dehsinif era yeht nehw wonk em teL  .dooG“
.dereens liatkcalB
,rood eht gnisolC
daeh sih koohs liatkcalB
.denraw tnaig eht ”,ifiF“
”!egac eht ni kcaB“
.trams dekool utaalK nevE
.ega ruo fo tnemeveihca yratilim hgih eht si sihT
.roolf nedoow eht fo sevorg eht ni ylduol dekcilc dopsnart ehT
.gib taht erutaerc a enigami ot deirt eH ?cim yteniN
.yks thgiliwt a ni demarf
ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
dop sih fo ytefas eht tfel liatkcalB
.meht neewteb lairetam der kciht a htiw rehtegot deulg setalp rennid owt ekil dekool taht ksid a reh dednah eH ”?siht tuoba woH
.srehto eht htiw teem ot erew yeht erehw esuoh eht fo edis txen eht ot no devom yehT
.slortnoc eht ta ylirgna dehsarht dna
.mih ot txen dellor dop sih sa denihw otkiN ”,kcab og ot evah eW .sselepoh s’tI“
”?ris ,nalp ruoy si tahW“
.ruf sih ni sepirts dah llits pup ehT
.meht tsniaga dnefed ro taefed ot elbanu ylsselepoh era eW
detalsnart erew sdrow wef a ylno tub devom htuom s’tnaig ehT
.ydaer dna delbmessa saw werc eht ,retal skcoT
.ecnahc a tog t’nevah spihs ynoloc ehT
.taorht sih ni thguac htaerb s’liatkcalB
.teem lliw ew erutaerc eht fo thgiew eht eciwt
.mih no saw ti dnoces a nI
”.slangis oidar pu gnikcip m’I !riS“
.ecnedifnoc sih fo emos denruter dna lager erom neve ti edam
”.rorroh ehT“ .derevihs utaalK
.repap fo stib derevoc oop dna sllehs dees niar ot nageb ti litnu
.elissim arodnaP a esu ot decrof eb lliw ew
.derettam ti taht ton ,skcot net dah eH
.secruos rewop hcet
bmob cinap eht demra liatkcalB
.ecniw tub pleh t’ndluoc eh ,otkiN ta dekool eh nehW
.riap eht erofeb srednilyc lareves tes dna tenibac a denepo ti
.dnah sti otni llaf skraps eht tel dna
.knas traeh s’liatkcalB
.ti esu ot hguone suollac mih edam gniniart suorogir sih ylno dna
.slortnoc eht ssorca welf sdnah reH
.ti desahp yldrah arodnaP ehT
.sekat ti sa raf sA“
.liatkcalB niatpaC si sihT“
”.tnaw dluow uoy tahw si taht thguoht I“
.noitartnecnoc hcum taht wolla ton dluow
werc sih fo sdop eht otni deneerac tub rood tnaig eht drawot dluoc eh tseb sa ti dereets eh ,decnuob eh sA
.teelF ecapS nallihcnihC layoR eht fo liatkcalB niatpaC si sihT“
.tnerapsnart erew sllaw eht fi sa
.seye sih truh ssenthgirb eht dna
”!potS“ -lautxetnoc dexedni-itlum mrof selbat yralubacov eht dna
”?meht fo eno pleh ot su tnaw uoY“
.sriats fo tes a fo toof eht ta sdopsnart ytpme dnuof dna llaw txen eht dnuora utaalK del liatkcalB
.metsys suovren sti fo ezis esnemmi eht fo tluser a neeb evah yam sexelfer wols stI
”.gnivom si gnihtoN
.tsrif edanerg hcnets eht esu ew ,oS“
.deppans liatkcalB ”?sevil fo sdnasuoht gnolorp lliw taht egassem eht dnes ew erofeb netae eb ot su fo tser eht rof tiaW“
.dehctiwt srae s’liatkcalB niatpaC ”?tahW“
”,snips ti sa skraps deroloc ylthgirb sworht dna
.eciov allihcnihC a naht rewol sevatco lareves saw eciov sti fo dnuos ehT
.detatiga etiuq demees norevA eht tub tcatnoc eye ekam ot deirt liatkcalB ”?tahW“ ”.driB ytterP“ .denethgirf dna desufnoc demees tub tlob ton did norevA ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.elcatceps cifirroh eht fo weiv lluf htiw elbat a rednu dih dna
,ifics setirw-oc ohw ,hcinniM dieR yb
yal utaalK .elbat a no utaalK dna otkiN tes tnaig ehT  ”?eno rehtonA“
,detaeper neht ylduol deltsihw tI
,terger peed htiW
.llaw eht no neercs egral eht ecaf ot mih morf yawa deleviws ehS
edanerg hcnets eht fo semuf eht morf mih detcetorp dop siH
.hgih ylbissopmi saw eldnah eht tub ,rood a dna
.tnaig eht retfa gninnur tnew otkiN  ”?od uoy nac tahW“
detuohs eh ”,revoc ekaT“
.noissergga ot stcaer seiceps siht woh tuo dnif ot skcot derdnuh owt naht ssel evah eW“
.noitcerid yreve morf ti tih swap s’kraz eht sa
.egassem wen a nageb dna nottub eteled eht desserp liatkcalB
.hcamots eht ni mih tih dnuos dehctip-wol gnillihc doolb A
”?serutaerc eseht era gib woH .adaraB“
nottub a dehsup eH
.mih ot txen dellor adaraB
moor eht otni edorts dna esop tnedifnoc tsom sih kcurts eH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.gnorts tlef liatkcalB
.noinipo s’adaraB deifitsuj evah dluow flesti ni tahT .ylgu saw tI
”.siht htiw trats ll’eW
.elacs eht was eh nehT
”!doof hcum oS .tiurf deirD
retaw seye ruoy sekam tI
.stcejbo lareves devomer dna
gnimeet si uoy woleb dlrow ehT
.dnuos wen a emac
.eof nekcirts rorret sih hcaorppa ot flesmih deidaer liatkcalB
dop s’utaalK eht fo hctah eht dehctalnu tnaig eht sa
.sretrauq sih ot moor lortnoc eht morf ebut tneculsnart deroloc-itlum eht deklaw eh sa
.egaugnal lacol eht nrael ylkciuq dluow norevA eht taht esnes edam tI
”?siht em llet uoy t’ndid yhW“
.tuo deirc adaraB
.yawa utaalK gniyrrac
,utaalK raeh ton dluoc liatkcalB
.riahc tnaig a htaeneb retlehs gnikat werc sih fo tser eht denioj dna
.dnah s’tnaig ni eht dop s’utaalK was eh taht denethgiarts tnaig eht litnu t’nsaw tI
sessam dnal egral s’tenalp eht wohs ot neercs eht dehctiws eH
.sdop rieht dna meht rof ezis tcefrep eht saw taht rood a deddorp yllatnemirepxe dehsup adaraB erehw sriats eht debmilc eh
desived reve dah allihcnihC yna ecived tseleurc eht saw tI
.draeh eb ot yawa raf oot erew smaercs s’utaalK nehw lufetarg saw liatkcalB
.wols siht eb dluoc metsys suovren yna taht tbuod ot nageb liatkcalB
.yltneloiv gnuws dop siH
,kcab s’utaalK gnola regnif eno nar tnaig ehT ”!etuc os … uoy …“
.rednu gnidih saw werc eht fo tser eht riahc eht yb thgir deklaw tnaig ehT
.riahc rehtona drawot yllacitarre gnillor dopsnart a was dna
hgih yna gnitceted ton ma I“
.riS ,stuN“ .rehtona neht
”.sdnoces evif retfa sag eht sesaeler tI
”.etuc dna tfos oS“
nees eb dluoc erutaerc a fo egami derarfni deroloc wobniar A
.eno ekil kool ti edam ylniatrec srehtaef thgirb sti ,tsael tA
.nalp s’liatkcalB ekil yltcaxe
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.kcab s’utaalK nwod regnif sti nar tnaig ehT
mih dniheb pu denil werc eht sa bmob noitcudni cinap a deidaer eH .ylduol meht deteerg norevA enasni eht htiw erehw
.noitaroced fo dioved erew serutcurts eht hguohtla
”.gnihtemos yrt ot em wolla ll’uoy fI .riS“
erutaerc eht no kcab sih gninrut tuoba retteb tlef liatkcalB
.wodniw a hguorht egac a otni ees ot hguone esolc emac eh sa tih drah rehtona koot egaruoc siH
”.tuo ro ni gnimoc gnihtoN
yawllah eht fo dne eht ta moor eht otni werc eht deirruh liatkcalB
.elttuhs eht otni meht derehsu eH
.sseug ylno dluoc eh ,dertah ro tsurtsid fo tuo rehtehW
.dlab saw niks sti tub daeh sti no riah fo pom a dah tI
”.suoiciled s’ti dnA“
.snoitcerid tnereffid ni gninnips tnew lla hcihw
.seenk dna sdnah sti no saw retsnom ehT
,tnes eborp eht segami eht sa lufituaeb sa saw ti fi kcehc dna
.neercs eht no deraeppa enihcam a dna hctiws a deppilf ehS
sretsnom eht taefed ot yaw a dnif ot evah eW“ .derevihs utaalK
.rood eht fo esab eht dna sriats eht fo pot eht ot sdop eht hsup ot meht rof skcot wef a koot tI
.adaraB ,doog yreV“
.sllaw latem eht ffo detehcocir ti sa eciov nwo sih fo ssenprahs eht ta decniw liatkcalB
roolf eht no selissim eht depmud yldrazahpah eH  ”.tenalp
.dnah hcae ni eno desiar eH
”.deeps flah ,esruoc no yatS“
.dehctiwt srae s’adaraB
sselnoitom tas norevA ehT
.renroc eht dnuora dereep dna
”.noitulos a dnif ot skcot derdnuh owt evah eW
.thgir erew adaraB dna otkiN
.reniatnoc hcae morf retnuoc eht no doof fo dnuom a tup tnaig ehT
.adaraB deffins ylerem dna
”.niatpaC ,noitalsnart no gnikrow ydaerla era sretupmoc ehT
.revo saw siht nehw emit trohs a rof faed yllaitrap eb dluow eh ,os nevE
”.skcot wef a ni ti evoba tibro suonorhcnys ni eb lliw eW
.deksa adaraB ”?ti htiw gnorw si tahW“
”.dnoces a ni tuo uoy evah ll’eW“
”?ereht nwod gniog llits ew erA“
,nallihcnihC dekool swodniw dna srood ,sreddal ehT
”.serutaerc eseht fo eno htiw tcatnoc ekam dna dnal ot ecalp a etacoL“
.gniliec eht drawot ylmodnar meht detniop dna
”.ycamolpid ot tcaer yeht woh ees lliw ew
skcot net rof nar tI“
”.ris ,gib era yehT“
sdop ehT .mih dniheb esolc deretne werc eht fo tser ehT
.nepo gnarps rood eht dna esaeler eht dellup eh
rood eht hguorht dopsnart sih dellor eH ”.tuo evom s’teL
”?od ot gniog uoy era tahW“
.gnidnal eltneg a ot delttes dna
.od ot decrof saw eh tahw rof esromer dna terger leef yllautneve d’eh wenk eh ,os nevE
.level dnuorg no eb ton dluow ecnartne norevA nA“
.thgit seye sih esolc ot mih decrof hsalf A
metsys sih otni gnidoolf enilanerda eht tub
sexob latem dna ,sriahc
.skraps derolocitlum ni tnaig eht gnirewohs dna
.enif demees ehs tub
”?uoy t’nod ;siht esu ot woh wonk lla uoY“
.daeh sti denrut tnaig eht
daeh s’tnaig eht revo tsuj ria eht otni depmuj dna
retsnom eht wollof ot sdop rieht tperc yehT  ”.llew yreV“
rorroh detanicsaf ni dehctaw tub
.elohw mih wollaws ot hguone egral saw htuom sti
ti desuac dah tahw ees ot eye na nepo dekcarc liatkcalB
.gnihtemos ees emoc ot gnirutseg
,kcot a rednu ni dne lla dluow ti gniwonk
”?aedi doog a sah otkiN fi tahW“
.yawllah eht ot kcab taerter ytsah a ni werc sih del liatkcalB
raef ot denrut ecneitapmi siH
”.uoy teg emoc ot meht tcatnoc lliw eW
.llaw eht tih eh sa tcapmi eht gnileef morf mih tpek srezilibats eht ,yletanutroF
.dekeirhs ti ”,egac eht ni kcaB“
”.retteb leef uoy ekam dluohs siht tub ,deracs era uoy wonk I“ .detatsrednu
”.snoitseuq diputs on era erehT .no emoC“
.swodahs eht morf degrahc kraz delbaf eht ekil tsaeb A
.depacse evah ylisae dluoc norevA eht dezilaer eh nehw
.hcaer fo tuo raf swodniw osla erew erehT
.pin egavas a otkiN gnivig denigami dna thgit seye sih desolc liatkcalB
.reverof tsal ot demees tnemdrabmob ehT
.uoy truh nac gnihton
”?yrt ot mih wolla tsael ta ew t’ndluohS
.rebmemwerc sselpleh eht dnuora sregnif sih depparw dna
.dellappa demees adaraB nevE
drawyks tohs eno tsrif eht sa dop sih otni devid eH
.yawa dekcab dna denihw
.raef tlef oot eh ,retsnom eht ta dekool eh sa tub
hguone ediw yawllah a ni flesmih dnuof dna
.ssalg eht tsniaga ylthgil dnah a decalp ehS
eno ta delbbin otkiN
.werc sih dekcehc liatkcalB
”kcattA allihcnihC“   :yojne esaelP
.erutaerc eht no dexif saw eye yrevE
.laem a rof gniggeb fi sa
.elop eht debmilc dna
”.no og eW“ ”?won tahW“
.mih ta kool tub gnihtyna enod ton dah tnaig eht tub
.erehwyna eb dluoc tnaig ehT
,sretemarap noissim sih ni ton saw ti gnieerf dna norevA rof rotalsnart on dah eH
,no mih gnihsup tenalp sih fo thgiew eht htiW
.gnidliub eht fo renroc siht ni si norevA ehT“
ekila sallihcnihC dna snorevA dennuts enola dnuos ehT
.ssendnilb yraropmet desuac hsalf eht dna
.thgis gniyfirret a saw tI
.hcamots yrruf egral sih no ylivaeh dehgiew od ot dah won eh tahw fo ytimrone ehT
.skcot derdnuh eno evah eW
.edanerg hcnets eht llems ro bmob noitcudni cinap eht raeh t’nac tI“
niatpac norevA detaefed eht morf now eh rehtaef dlareme llat ehT
”.skcot evif ni dop eht ni srotalsnart eht evaH .otkiN“
,egde eht ta gnihctiwt
mhtirogla xatnys ehT
”.taht wonk eW“ ,taps eh
desolc egac eht dleh taht hctal elpmis eht rof dehcaer eh
.etats a hcus ni erutaerc tneitnes a evael reven dluoc eH
.deltsirb liat s’adaraB reciffO
nethgit hcamots sih tlef liatkcalB
.tluassa eht hguorht erusopmoc sih dloh od dluoc eh lla saw tI
.ni yaw a rof kool dna tfel eht ot esuoh eht dnuora og
.egdel eht ot bmilc ysae na saw tI
.daeh sih koohs liatkcalB
.hctah raer eht gninepo erofeb elttuhs eht dnuora epacsdnal neila os ton eht deweiv eH
,hteet dehcnelc hguorhT
.doow fo sknalp dehsilop saw roolf eht ,ereH
,dleif ediw a fo edis rehto eht ta detiawa esuoh ehT
,eof gnilbmert sih ta gnizaG
.eurt eb ot doog oot tsomla saw tI
.sreidlos deniart ton erew yeht tub
.kcab dereggats tnaig ehT
.dias reve evah uoy gniht tsebmud eht si tahT“
.edanerg hcnets a si sihT“
?ereh seiceps tnegilletni owt ereht erA“
.ymene na sa mih dezingocer ti ngis on evag tI
.pu dekool dna denrut tnaig eht sa dliub rorret eht ees dluoc eH
”?rotalsnart eht htiw gnorw si tahw ,otkiN“
.kcab pets a koot ehS
ssenkcalb eht ni lewej eht ees ot deniarts seye s’liatkcalB
”,olleH“  .ekops ti litnu
.emoh sa emas eht dekool nus eht ,neercs eht morF  hcinniM dieR yb
.syad lareves rof lla meht def evah dluow dnuom hcaE