.ni emoc uoy erehw s'taht 'nA"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,golb rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
".ffirehS eht llac 'na
ti etib nac yeht os ,tfos 'nihtemos esu attoG
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,renwot-attuo na s'eH"  "?haeY"
ot yaw a mih dnif dluoc I desoppus I
-tekcop tsaerb sih ref sehcaer eh 'nA
,dlog ni skcub derdnuh a htiw dnuora sklaw ydoboN .yltcaxE"
.ti ni ecnedifnoc emos evah attog'y
laer s'ti kniht me' tel ,nioc eht ekat kram eht teL
hguone ecin saw dna ,ti sdeen ylsuoivbo ohw enoemos't boj taht evig I t'ndluohs yhw 'nA"
suoreneg 'nileef saw I ,woN"  .kcab og t'nac I
,sraluger ruo toN"
.rehtegotla nwot piks ot ton fi ,pohs eht evael ot hguone gnol ref
,net ot tnuoc I 'na
esuac' ,saw I taht rats ykcul sih 'na
.tnemhsilbatse nwo ym ni skcub derdnuh a tsomla attuo
,rotaneS ekaf a ssap annog rey fi ,kool
,kaeb ym tirg I oS"  ".tihs oN"
s'ti emit yreve 'na
".eno rehto eht llup ,haeY"
.yaw thgir eht skooblleps kcap't mih 'nihcaet rey elihw thginot nac uoy 'nihtyreve tuo dnif
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
enaJ tniaS knaht ot mih dlot I 'na ,noonretfa siht
.ti ees ot ksa I oS .rab eht dniheb hcum taht peek t'nod diS sa erus I dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
"?ssenisub ruo tuo tar ot droffa t'nac dna
?ti t'nia ,edisni eht no leets parcs si sruoY
'nileef m'I ecno 'na
".ereh draob 'n' moor nrae
".ton rehtar yllaer d'eh syas 'na
,ztaK xelA yb ”egnahC pmuhC“ saw sihT
".mih attuo lanimirc laer a ekam ll'ew ebyaM
,mih ot yas I ekilydal erom etim a
".ssob eht er'uoy ,thgirrA"
"?haey ,erofeb klofnoil htiw ecid deyalp ev'uoY"  ".ruetamA"
"...ylno ,ssob ,gnorw ton reY"
.tnemailraP edisyaW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ztaK xelA yb ”egnahC pmuhC“
".secalp rehto ni ,haey tub
.wal eht fo seicrem rednet eht no mih worht naht od't sgniht retteb dah I
si yrots s’yadoT dna
".rotaneS a rof egnahc ekam nac I fi em sksa eh dna..."  ztaK xelA yb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”egnahC pmuhC“   yojne esaelP
,spots eh neht 'na-
,ssob ,evah I esruoC'"
,ruf sih rednu elap elttil a tnew
,elihw a rof hsif thguac-hserf a ekil em ta derats eh ,lleW"  "?taht ot
mih hguorht thgir ees d'dik a ti tuoba ysmulc os 'nieb s'eh dnA
"?rae yhctiwt a htiw eno teem revE"
em tfirg 'a'niyrt s'eh niatrec rof wonk I won oS
,pal ruo otni thgiarts llaf ot
,em no sffirehS eht llac t'nod esaelp
,dias eh neht 'na
;tfihs ruoy no s'eH
.s'tterraG sa doog sa s'pihsnamnep sih fi ees 'nA
yas eh d'tahw 'nA !haH"  ".ti yub dna
".siloporteM ot yaw eht no 'nissim tnew tterraG 'lo ecnis reve moor kcab eht krow ot wen enoemos ref 'nikool neeb ev'uoY .ssa ym suoreneG"
,dias eh ,tsrif ta mih raeh t'ndluoc tsomla I 'na
.ti dah yug sihT"  ".llet a
".mih fo esuac' su 'nidnif pu dne dluoc ohw
.rekihctih flowerew ,flowcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
,mih retfa s'ohw onnud ew
,yademos levon taht hsinif ll’yeht sraews ohw
,elihw a rof yats ot erehwemos dedeen eh fi ,tcaf nI