.tnedicca ciffart daB“
.won saw eh tahw s’tahT
.ytefas tnanimatnoc lacisyhp naht rehtar ytefas lanoitome rof ylno ,niaga ,gniniart—
.pu kcab neht dna tsehc s’zaR ot nwod gnikcilf seye sih
,setamssalc ym saw ti
.gel detius-citsalp sih gnola wap a debbur zaR
,kcab eht ni renroc enots eht ot eert renroc eht morf retemirep ediw a
.tuo dab yllaer gnihtyna tog srepus ehT
,yenom ekam ot tuo tsuj enoyreve
”.dlawenurG ni evil yehT“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.no sgnirevoc daeh rieht tup ekirB dna eh sa zaR ot gninokceb ,dias eh
.trac eht fo tnorf eht debbarg dna
”.doog on s’ti won tub ,emit elohw eht ereh gnivil erew ew dna ,reniatnoc delaes a ni s’ti
.telbat eht pu dleh kiliK
.renroc a dnuora nav eht dediug
?ti eveileb uoy naC
.zaR ot kcab dellac ekirB ”?taht tuob’ woH
.tnemom a rof eldnah rood eht no deregnil wap siH
.nodnet dereves yltraP“
.tius citsalp nwo sih fo noitcetorp eht morf mih ta dennirg
,rood eht dleh ekirB elihw pu trac eht dehsup neht ,ti denetsaf dna
,sretlif eht gninimaxe
”?ereht gniod bal eugalp a si lleh eht tahW
,TME na sa nrow d’eh seitoob deddap eht fo mih dednimer tI
”.rolesnuoc tnemtsevni na si mom rehto ym dna knab a ta PV a si mom ym tub
,elpoep htiw gnilaed dnuorgkcab sih tuoba tol a zaR ot deklat d’yehT .saw ti erehT
.elcsum flac dna sdap sih hguorht pu delgnit niap railimaF
,luferac eb attog eW
.ffo gnirevoc daeh sih koot dna kcab deppets zaR
,dias lerriuqs eht ”,haey ,hO“ ”.zaR m’I
nav eht tup ekirB ”.ti si sihT
,gnilaeh dedeen ohw
,esuoh eht fo edis eht dnuora kcab dednetxe dna eert tsomthgir eht dednuorrus epat ecilop wolleY
.dnuorg eht gnola gnilffuhs seitoob citsalp
,kaeb derracs dna kcen niht a htiw erutluv tauqs a
?gnihtemos ro rekorbkcots a saw sretsaM .rM fi wenk ohw
,gnidliub eht fo renroc eht dnuora deirruh tar gib eht
.esuoh emarf nedoow elttil taen a tas sehcnarb sti ni pu dna
”.uoy rof epocsorcim taht teg ll’I dna—
.kcab kcilf srae s’zaR ekam ot hguone duol eciov hsarb a dah ekirB ”?suovren uoY“
,dloG lleyK ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb ”pU gninaelC“
epocsorcim a s’erehT“
”,gninaelc eht od tsuj nac ew dnA“
,tnorf eht ni owt eht fo rehtie naht regral saw llaw kcab eht fo retnec eht ta kao ehT
”.suseJ“ .decniw leD
,kiliK ,ssob wen siH
,noos elbasu dna kcab tnemesab ruoy evah ll’uoY“
.esuoh eht fo renroc kcab eht dednuor yehT .dias kiliK
.thguoht ni tsol ,rood kcab eht ta gnirats llits
?lerriuqs eht ,hcraM deR ,yug taht rebmemer uoY“
si yrots s’yadot dna
,wap a pu dleh dna denrut tar ehT
foor eht fo tuo gnikop seert egral htiw tliub sesuoh dna
.esae ta elpoep gnittup ta taerg neeb dah
.rehtegot depsalc swap sih
”.did ew boj eht gniod rof su deknaht ,swap s’enoyreve koohs ,retfa dnuora kcuts
.dekcalc kaeb s’erutluv ehT ”.erus ,eruS“
secivres ecnalubma teercsid dellac dna
gnidliub eht ot txen yawevird eht otni dellup pukcip kcalb A ”.ekirB s’ereht ,yeH“
.rood rac a morf pu nrot latem fo eceip a no dednal dna deppils I .ris ,oN“
.kiliK ot daeha dellac neht
mih ta delims lerriuqs ehT
.mih dniheb gnirettulf liat delevehsid sih ,denokceb eH
.ecafrus eht gnola swalc deparcs dna
”.seirevoceR“ ni ”R“ eht gnirucsbo
.tuo dellup yeht ,edis regnessap tnorf eht otni flesmih delkcub dah kiliK nehW
.gnikool yllaer ton
.cilbup ni tuo stnedicca rieht evah t’ndid elpoep hcir
.rood kcab eht ta gnirats
,derettum erutluv eht
”.roolf eht ffo pu ti gnignops ro sllaw eht ffo ffuts elbirroh gniparcs eb t’now ew dna ,sdiulf ydob tuo ffins ot evah t’now uoy tub
.god dna srentrap sih htiw emoh gniyats yltnerruc si dna ainrofilaC ni sevil eH
”?setunim wef a rof yug siht ot klat dna ereh tuo yats I naC“
”.pu wohs ew emit eht yb enog gnol era srepus ehT“
.seenk sih dnuora pu liat sih delruc eH
.noitidnoc taht no yregrus sih rof diap dah
telbat sih pu thguorb kiliK ”.yecid sdnuoS
hguorht snoisses sti fo hcae ta detcurtsni sah dna ,pohskrow gnitirw yrruf laitnediser tsrif eht ,RWAR etaerc depleh eH .9002 fo levoN yaG tseB rof drawA wobniaR eht now-oc
”.sretsaM .rM ,melborp oN .yakO“
.enohp sih tuo dellup kiliK
.kcab eht dnuora emoc ot evah uoY“
,kcab srae sih dial dna detrons zaR
.12 eßartS-nehcdläwretsniG“
.spets elpuoc a koot dna teef sih revo no seitoob citsalp eht dellup zaR
.dnuora nrut t’ndid kiliK ”?haeY“ .dias eh
.enecs eht no tsrif erew eW
ll’ti tub ,klaw nac I won dna ,erom eerht rof sehcturc ,shtnom xis rof ti ffo yats ,yregrus teg ot dah I
.yenom taht htiw od ot tahw tuoba gnihton
”…tsuj ,ereht ni dnif uoy revetahw ,kooL“
,dlohserht eht revo trac eht gnihsup saw eh sa tub
:ereh tuo emoc ot llac hcum dah t’ndah eH
.seitoob citsalp s’zaR ta nwod dekool eH
”.gnihtemos ro muls a ekil si siht kniht ylbaborp yeht oS“
,taht em dlot yeht ,og ot sah nehctik eht ni doof eht llA“
,moc.dloglleyk.www ta elbaliava si skoob sih dna mih tuoba
.dias xof eht ”,enif m’I“
,swodniw roolf-dnuorg ssorca dehcterts
”.thgir lla ,esuoh lerriuqs a s’tahT“
skrap gib dna sesuoh llams hguorht yaw sti dnuow nav eht sa
.zaR ot kcab neht dna
.ynapmoc eht detrats I ecnis ruof enod ev’I“ .dias kiliK
”,nav eht morf mih dellac I“
”.tnemom yna ta tuo evig thgim gel ym fi TME na eb t’nac I
.dehgual ekirB ”.driht ym ylno si sihT“ ”?snialliv-
.yad tsrif ym s’tI
!aH ?ecalp sih s’tahT“
.dnuorg eht otni nwod gnidael yawriats dessecer a ssorca dna
,ssob oS“ .tnorf eht ot kcab denrut tar ehT ”.dooG“
,srebmun eht t’nsaw tI
,struh ti…naem I .enif eb ll’tI
”.desu ecilop eht tahw s’taht
.delkcuhc ekirB ”.looC“
spot ,owt—yad a ni pu denaelc lla siht teg ot gniog er’eW
.debborht toof siH
”.ecnanif yduts ot em detnaw yeht ,yllautcA“
.pirts orcleV a htiw pot eht ta delaes tI
:srotinaj deifirolG
”.og s’tel ,ereh m’I ,ereh m’I“
,m’I .eciton t’ndid I .looc s’tI“
.taht od ot ton denrael dah zaR
”.ynialliv-repus fo debtoh a yllaer t’nia nilreB fo trap sihT“
”.ti tuoba wonk ot tnaw t’nod I .ti tnaw t’nod I
”…siht tup ot trats nac uoy dna
.tlahpsa eht otni nwod ti desserp xof ehT ”.eniF“
.rebmun ym uoy evig ll’yeht dna seirevoceR llac nac uoy…tub
,tluciffid eb nac ti ,sevitaler dna sdneirf htiw wonk I ,naem
,kao eht fo tfel eht ot llaw kcab eht nI
,tnemom taht ni tub
.raeg citsalp sih ni nehw sehcti erongi ot flesmih deniart d’eh tub ,dehcti rae s’zaR ”.hU“
,slevon dna seirots sih rof drawA ltoyoC a dna sdrawa rojaM asrU evlewt now sah ohw
.elims eniuneg a ekil dekool tahw delims lerriuqs eht
”.elpoep gnipleH“ ”.siht
esirprus sih ot dnuof zaR dna
”.elkna ym fo kcab eht pu decils dna citsalp eht hguorht dehcnup ,thgir tsuj delgnA
”.orcleV eht ni thguac ruf ruoy teg t’noD“
.dellac eh ”,ekirB ,yeH“
.ysmilf erom dna rethgil ylno
od nac I tuB“
.9102
,llam gnippohs gib eht tsap neht dna sgnidliub lairtsudni kcirb ytrid eht hguorht tuo yaw eht lla
”.sretsaM leD .leD  ,hu ,m’I
”.ti htiw laed nac I tub
,dias ekirB ”,ykcul er’uoY“
.sknahT“ .deddon zaR
thgirpu srae sih tpek xof ehT
pmar eht revo pu depmub ti dna ,kcab devaw yehT
”.rood tnorf eht no prat taht fo ezis eht tuoba si tnemtrapa yM
,lerriuqs eht nwod demlac d’eh tsael tA
.etsaP tunlaW yeretnahC eht neve
taht swodniw llams htiw sesuoh yrots-ruof ykriuq
”.elddoc ot sevitaler ypeew oN“ .dedda kiliK
.gnol oot ylthgils elzzum sih dna depmarc eb dluow srae sih tnaem hcihw ,ledom cificeps-xof evisnepxe erom eht naht rehtar ,ledom dinac cireneg a ekil dekool tI
,rood kcab eht hguorht tuo dna ni teg nac uoY“
.erom yas ot mih rof gnitiaw
”.og nac ew ereh steg ekirB s’nooS“
.taht tuoba doog tlef eh taht
,og meht dehctaw zaR
etavirp ni meht dah yehT
.tleb taes sih delkcubnu kiliK ”.puY“ .kraP ni
,deriter d’ohw ollidamra eht ,yecnuahC woh tuoba hcum os deklat yeht esuaceb yltsom ,ti dekil yllaer meht fo rehtien taht noisserpmi eht nettog d’eh dna
.taorht sih deraelc zaR
.syorudroc dna trihs deralloc wolley elap a ni renroc eht dnuora gninnur emac
.esnes yna ekam t’nseod tsuj tI
.elzzum dednetxe eht
I…ti tuoba klat ot tnaw uoy fI“
"noitisoP fo tuO" levon demialcca sih dna
.lliw ew ,ezilirets nac ew revetahw taht syug eht llet ll’I dnA“
,edisni sloop fo thgil gniremmihs eht htiw sesuoh retto yrots-eerht gib
”?amuart fo derit teg tsuj uoY“
”.kcab tuo esuoheert eht ni gnivil neeb ev’I
.7991 ecnis ,daer taht srettel eht woleb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.swap sih gnurw leD
”.uoy fo duorp eb tsum stnerap ruoY“
,emit tsrif eht roF
.noitanimatnoceD enecS amuarT dna emirC :noceD STC
,elbatrofmoc leef dluow snetram dna slesaew dna sexof erehw segassap worran dna syawllah evah dluow wenk zaR
rettiwT no mih wollof nac uoy dna
,sriats s’ereht dna nehctik eht ot sdael ti
.sevolg sih rof stekcop sih dekcehc xof ehT ”.haN“
.elohnottub pot eht otni denetsaf neeb dah nottub dnoces eht elihw ralloc eht fo renroc a no
.gnixaler mih ees ot desaelp saw zaR dna ,dehgual lerriuqs ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
zaR naht redlo sraey ytnewt tuoba lerriuqs der a sa tsuj tekcop sih ni dnuora gud dna
.meht ssorca epat etihw dna der thgirb eht
eh sa deltsihw ekirB ”?frodsnhaR“
.pu denaelc s’tnemesab eht litnu rood tnorf eht dliuber t’now yehT .yrroS
”?keew tsal pu mih dekcip nexiV suoiciV
”?ereht fo tuo tnaw uoy gnihtyna ereht sI“
”.frodsnhaR ni pu ,smoor owt ,tnemesaB“
,gnorw denottub neeb dah trihs sih taht deciton zaR
.meht ta evaw dluoc tar nworb llat a os desuap dna
,ecnuo na ythgie stsoc ffuts tahT
,latem eht tsniaga gniw a deppat eH
.esle gnihtyna od ot yenom hcum oot yllaretil dah uoy nehw did uoy gnihtemos yporhtnalihp ,sexat fo tuo teg ot yaw a saw ytirahC
”?gnol siht gniod neeB“
,em tsuj saw taht ,naem I“
.daeh sih koohs zaR
”,ecno etoyoC knilB tem I“
,nav gib eht tsniaga denael erutluv ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
gnola gnignah nottub pot eht
”.dlrow siht ton tsuj s’tI“
.dnuorg eht ot llaf ti tel dna ffo epat eht deppir kiliK
.liaj ni dna evila llits saw nos sih esuaceb ’,uoy dniheb lla‘ toN
.seye eht ni mih dekool leD
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
noitamrofni eroM
,nav eht fo kcab eht pu denepo yehT
.ytilibaticxe larutan rieht fo esuaceb slerriuqs ni sserts koolrevo ot ysae saw tI
”.ti rof tuo eye na peek ll’I“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,retal setunim wef A
.meht pleh llits dluoc eh dna
.gniniart sih morf kcab sdrow dellup zaR ”.hu ,lleW“
.tol a esuoh ruoy ekil I“
.temleh drazahoib a zaR gnissap
.ylthgils tseretni s’zaR derrits tahT
.ti tuoba yrrow t'nod tub“
llew sa no sih werht xof eht oS
.skao egral eerht tem sllaw esohw esuoh enots a
’.bal eugalp‘ siht tuoba su llet
”,yaw taht ti ekil I“
,sdleihs citsalp kciht eht
.mih dniheb ti desolc dna rood kcab eht dessorc eh sa pmil ot ton deirt zaR ,llitS
,wap sih htiw ngis ”KO“ na edam dna kcab denrut eh retal tnemom A
”?mH“ .mih no desucof seye s’leD ”.hO“ ”?sretsaM .rM“
”,trac eht evah s’teL“
.eert sih ot kcab deklaw dna
,seorehrepus yna teem t’ndluow eh ebyaM
,sriats eht no detser seye s’zaR
.liat yhsub sih dnuora palf liat eht llup ot kcab dnuora dehcaer neht
.tnemom a rof desuap dna citsalp eht ni dlof a fo eerf srae sih fo eno krow ot daeh sih denrut eh
.hcum os rettam ot mees t’ndid taht
,dellac eh ”,setunim eviF“
”.raey a elpuoc a steg eh ,reporp nilreB ni nwod noced STC seod enim fo dneirF
.rood tnorf elbuod ediw eht ssorca dehcterts prat citsalp gib a dna
,pleh dedeen ohw ereh elpoep llits erew esehT
.tuo tsrub yeht retal tnemom a dna ,lerriuqs eht ni pu gnidliub sdrow eht sreksihw sih ni leef dluoc eH .detiaw zaR
”.ti htiw od ot tnaw uoy tahw ediced nac uoy nehT
,daeh sih koohs leD ”.sknahT“
.deddon—leD—lerriuqs ehT
.tey gat eman a evah t’nod I wonk I“ ,dias eh ”,yeH“
.toof taht fo erac ekat uoY“
,dias eh ”,ni og ot deen I“
”.ruof-ytnewt m’I“ ”?uoy era dlo woH“
.deksa kiliK ”?toof eht s’woH“
.edistuo dekool dna wodniw eht tsniaga rae sih denael zaR ”.taerG“ ”.nialliv-repus a s’boj tsrif ruoY“
,sregnif sih neewteb cirbaf eht debbur xof ehT
”.oga sraey neetxis ,neetfif tfel ehs ,hu ,mom siH
,emit tsrif eht roF
,esuoh sih ta pu dekool eh ,no og t’ndid zaR nehw tub
.truh syawla ylbaborp
.mih dna em tsuj saw ti ,haeY“
.slatipsoh nwo rieht ot tnew dna
.elims tseb sih no tup zaR
.eromyna hcum ti esu t’nseod ylbaborp eh—
”?ereht ni s’tahw swonk ohW
”.sraey ruof rof taht erofeb TME na saw I tub ,emit tsrif ym si sihT“
?sseug I ,evitcepsrep otni ,hU“
.gniog eb d’yeht erehw s’tahT
,yawa thgir gnihtyna yas t’ndid lerriuqs ehT
:yojne esaelP   .dloGlleyK@ ta
”.oot ,orcleV ot ruf tsoL“ .tius sih fo tnorf citsalp
”?dad…sih erew uoY“
,detarefilorp epat ecilop eht ,esuoh eht fo edis eht dnuorA
dloG lleyK yb ”pU gninaelC“
.sregnif evif lla pu dleh neht
.esuoh sih ta niaga dekool leD ”.puY“
,niaga teiuq llef zaR
”.niaga sknahT“ ”.wonk t’nod I
,eert eht fo esab eht ta doots lerriuqs ehT
,deppots nav eht taht eseht fo eno yb saw tI
.htaerb rof desuap ylerab lerriuqs ehT
.tius citsalp sih gnola wap detaoc-citsalp eno debbur zaR
”pU gninaelC“ saw sihT
.dnuorg eht ta nwod neht dna rood kcab eht drawot dekool lerriuqs ehT ”.ebyaM .oN“
nialp eht revo wap kcalb a dehsurb zaR
.stekcub eht dna srenaelc eht dleh taht trac gib eht gnihsup zaR
,sevlow rof smoor nepo gib htiw sesuoh yrots-owt gnilwarps
;tnar eht fo tser eht ffo tib eH ”.ti detah I
”,thgif eht gnirud dellips ev’thgim sgnihT“
.seciffo seirevoceR eht dniheb deraeppasid dna
.krap llams a fo ezis eht dray a dah hcae taht sesuoh regral wef a tsap neht dna
,toof sih derujni d’eh nehw eerged sih hsinif og ot mih detnaw d’yehT
.taes s’revird eht otni dils ekirB elihw kcab eht gnikat zaR
eh dnA .srac fo tuo elpoep eht fo emos detropelet ,depleh eH
.bal eugalp a pu gninaelc er’eW ?ykcuL“
.bal nialliv-repus a tsuj s’ti tub ,haeY“
tsuj ,oN“ .niaga dias leD ”,oN“
”.gnihtyna no pets t’noD
,nav eht otni delip yehT
”!era syug uoy erehT“
”.reeb a rof uoy teem dna nwod tis ot yppah eb d’I
,esle gnihtynA .epocsorcim eht tnaw tsuj I—
repus ynam od syug uoY“
”.net saw eh nehw yadhtrib sih rof mih ot ti evag I
.lausu erew thguoht zaR naht rediw ylthgils erew seye sih dna
”.tnatropmi gnihtyna od ro nur ot evah t’nod I sa gnoL“
.detiaw ti ssorca epat etihw dna der fo pirts eno htiw rood elgnis a
.gnidliub eht fo renroc a gnimrof ro
,rood tnorf deprat-citsalp eht tA
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,dloG lleyK yb
.ytic eht ni evil I
.sdrow rof deparcs lerriuqs eht elihw detiaw zaR ”…s’tahT
.ti eveileb t’nac llits I .nialliv-repus A“
”.taht no pu uoy ekat tsuj thgim I .sknahT“
.yb deraor sraC ”?suovren uoY“
.daerb dna etsap nroca fo llems eht thguac zaR dna ,delahxe leD
,oot ,ylkciuq gnihtaerb saw eH
,mih dehctaw leD
.raeg rieht debbarg srehto eht elihw kcab gnuh zaR dna
”.erofeb stius nrow ev’I .haey ,haeY“
,yb dellor sesuoH
.egelloc hguorht yawflah tuo deppord I“
.netfo ereht pu og ot teg t’noD“
,lerriuqs eht ot spets wef a retfa ylevislupmi denrut eH
,raeg drazahoib rieht htiw esuoh eht ot pu dedarap yehT