,sreenignE dna stsitneicS
gniyalf yknaj taht llA
.srehtaef gninihs yllacitsejam htiw
,sgnilbis redlo ruoy lla devivrus dah koob sihT
,smeti eerht no dediced yeht litnu
,pihs eht no kcaB
.raos ot elba erew uoy sthgieh taerg tahw ot dna
.otni esir ot yks detimilnu na dna
.pets hcae htiw hgih yllarutannu seenk ruoy esiar ot
evoba pu ria eht otni uoy deirrac dniw eht ekil meht ni ylnepo hturt eht deirrac sdrow s'rehtaf ehT
,yad lanif eht fo sruoh gninrom ylrae eht ni devirra edir ruoy nehw oS
.ssecorp eht ni stnetnoc sti yortsed ton ot luferac
?thgir ,ereht pu lios dna dnuorg on saw erehT
.esruoc sti tes dah pihs eht ecno
,saw taht telkoob elttil siht osla tub
,rehtom ruoy os ,uoy tub esle enoyna ot ruomalc duol dna yvaeh htiw epolevne eht revo dnah ot desufer dna lufitud yrev saw noegip eht taht tcaf eht morf llew sa
dna sgniw ruoy gnidnetxe
yoj fo sraet rieht kcab dloh ot elbanu woN
,dael ot denrut dah yeht ekil niks ruoy no deggard
.srepapswen dlo ni
,etad erutraped lanif eht erofeb raey a flah tuoba ,nehT
:smeti esoht fo hcae fo gninaem eht gninialpxe
- yaw emas eht tlef thgis siht dessentiw ohw enoyreve yhw nialpxe dluoc
,noitacude lacisyhp fo raey elohw A
seldnub-repapswen elttil eht gnipparwnu retfa
tnarg siht ni recnad enol a
:saw werc detceles eht fo noisserpmi tsrif ruoy gnorw woh
,swodniw eht hguorht rellams werg ylwols elbram eulb eht dna
,stnuts eseht fo lla ni
tneserp ot elba erew uoy llA
,ecneuqesnoc a sa taht dnA
,eno ht8 ro ht7 ruoy retfa ekaceseehc fo ecils REHTONA tae ylbissop t'ndluoc uoy taht dna
emoc dah uoy raf woh wohs ot
.ssenkcis gnimool a fo eid ot dnuob ton
,sevitaler ruoy fo eno osla ton
,srehtaef ruoy nevE
,swobniar eht fo sruoloc lla ni srehtaef dna skaeb fo llaw a neeb tsuj evah dluow ti ,esiwrehto
.ereht nosrep ni uoy teem ot trop-ecaps eht ot meht gnitivni yb
,srehtaef etihw gnitsartnoc dna
,epacse sih dna erutseg gniwob elttil a edam noegip eht ,neht dnA
teef ruoy gnisiar morf uoy gnippots
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
elpoep rehto htiw ni dehcrep ot
,yawllah eht nwod kcab deklaw uoy
...secein dna swehpen dna snisuoc dna sretsis dna srehtorb dna stnua dna selcnu ruoy
,nwot eht fo klat eht otni riaffa etavirp rehtar yllanigiro
dna erutraped ruoy retfa nrob erew ohw secein dna swehpen weN
,lortnoc fo tuo tnew sgniht esac ni htaed depacse evah dluoc reven eh
.etalocohc fo srab deilppus eht fo eno no snolat ruoy teg ot erutrot trohs siht ot gnieerga ylno
.eert ylimaf gnisaercni reve ruoy fo trap won
,raf pets ot dah ylekil rehpargotohp ehT
?detsat taht woh wenk neve ohw dna
.decifircas dah uoy tahw fo foorp
evoba morf gnillaf spordniar tsrif eht
.serutseg dekcohs neve dna ssendas
."egdelwonk cisab" sa debircsed saw tahw ot pu thguac yllanif dna
enalp eht fo swodniw eht fo eno fo tuo ezag tsrif eht tuB
,tnemeticxe dna yoj fo ynohpocac a
,niarg-tsud a fo ezis eht neve ton
,hguorht tuc saw ecalp siht ot uoy dnuob dah taht droc-lacilibmu eht ekil tlef ti
,oidar deriuqca ylwen a ni denoitnem saw noissim eht ecno
meht nihtiw segamad citeneg on
gniffuh dna gnipsag
,neht kcab dnatsrednu t'ndid yllaer uoy tcejorp emos rof llA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
,elbram etihw dna eulb A
:ylimaf elohw ruoy ot rettel eht tneserp ot elbat-tsafkaerb eht ot deredro tog uoy
,llarevo ecaps laiciffo eht ni uoy was yeht sa
,repap suoiretsym siht tuoba
,emoc dah emit eht nehw dnA
?eb ti t'ndluow yhw ynA
.mraf eht fo sdleif eht no yad rehtona rof pu gniydaer
.decitonnu niamer ton did hcrop tnorf eht no noitommoc ehT
,niaga dedracsid dna tuoba deklat
,detcelloc erew saedi ynam oS
,nosirapmoc ni sselgninaem dna gnissarrabme tlef
gnikeep nageb foor siht rednu kaeb rehto yreve ylgnimees elihw senil eht revo derednaw seye ruoy
noissim eht fo ssergorp eht htiw etad ot pu meht fo lla tpek dah rehtaf yloh eht woH
,ega hgih rieht rof tcepser gnidnameD
,ecalperif eht ni rotisiv elbisneherpmocni siht dracsid naht rehtar teY
,evitcepsrep s'redistuo na morf dekool evah tsum uoy yllis woH
,ereht nwod erehwemos saw emoh ruoy ,eruS
?detalernu tsomla dna
,eman ruoy ot desserdda saw taht epolevne nA
,noitom tfiws eno ni sgniw etihw gnol sih gnidlofnu erofeb
.evoba sehcaer sseldne eht otni raos ot uoy detivni taht
?emoh ruoy osla ereht nwod esle gnihtyreve t'nsaw tub
”sgniW deppilC“   yojne esaelP
,seno dlo eht woH
.tsafkaerb ruoy morf yawa uoy gard ot dah
:no hctac ot hcum os tey
.sledoM dna setelhtA
s'!hhhS yarts emos yb nekorb yllanoisacco ylno
esle enoyreve rof
od dluoc uoy sgniht eht lla tuoba gnikniht dnA
,elcihev eht fo knurt eht otni
:yenruoj rieht otno meht htiw ekat ot gniog erew yeht sotnemem eht tneserp ot ecnahc eht koot srebmemwerc eht fo tol a
.uoy nees neve reven suht dah
dedivorp ehs litnu
,tlef ecneirepxe siht sa lufrewop dna euqinu sA
,noisufnoc htiw gnidlofnu elcatceps siht dehctaw
enohp a nwo t'ndid ylimaf ruoY
sgnignoleb ruoy teg ot
,srenedrag ,srepeekraB
.setadidnac eht fo hcae fo
,tnatropmi ron ,tnaveler rehtien saw noitamrofni sihT
eb dluoc ti lufsserts woh dnatsrednu ot saw dnoces
.noitanitsed lanif rieht ees dluow
,snevaeh suoigiler eht ot gniog ton erew uoY
uoy gnirad fi sa tsomla ,deeps gnitnelernu na ta yb welf emiT
.srehtorb ynam ruoy htiw moorhtab eht neve dna ,moor ruoy
noitacifilauqsid rieht gniyfingis
,redneg ,ega fo sseldrager
,yad elohw a nekat evah tsum tnenitnoc eht flah revo evird siht hguoht nevE
saes gniyaws otni nrut yam sdnal nerrab eht taht os sdees eht gniwos ro
,tenalp eht ot nwod kcab tnes dna devomer erew ro
,emit fo tset eht dnats dluow egatireh citeneg ruoy ylno ton fi
stnerap ruoy yb ylesolc dewollof
,yllatnem flesruoy eraperp ot
noitanibmoc elbarised tsom eht sa pu-ekam citeneg ruoy deulav dah tnemnrevog eht fo
.snoitareneg ynam ,ynam ,ynam rof
modnar ta nesohc erew uoy
tuoba gniklat saw eh ohw langis ot fi sa
,uoy fo tnorf ni llits efil elohw ruoy dah uoY
.kcul dna egatireH
,repap fo eceip tnatropmi yrev A
ereh thguorb gnieb
,epolevne eht nepo deppir uoy
,emit tsal eht naht tluciffid ssel ton osla tub
.esromer yna tuohtiw
knab atad emoneg eht esuaceb ,egatireH
demussa evah tsum enoyreve ,tcepsorter ni ,taht detsat reve dah uoy gnihtyna fo hcum os tcaf nI
.ksat emas eht od ot noisiv fo dleif ruoy otni
daer ylerab dluoc ohw enoemos ot
rethgifeseehC yb
:uoy sa emas eht erew lla yeht
.tsap eht fo selat dna seirots htiw rehtegot gnola dessap
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
evloser yrassecen eht dah yeht rehtehw tset ot ro diarfa ''sdrib-ybab"
.egadneppa yna ro sgniw daerps ot ecaps yna ylerab htiw ,sretrauq dna syawllah ynit ni
- llew taht eraf ton did srehtO
.emit tsal eht rof emoh fo thgis a hctac ot
,sessalg gnidaer kciht sih dniheb desucof dna nrets
dnoces gnissap hcae rof thgif ot
- spihs htiw trop a ekil kool ti did ron ecaps ni rehtien saw ti hguoht neve
seip dna sekac erom htiw
.staem ruoy ezirednet ot saw srehtorb ruoy fo laog niam eht ekil kool ot detrats yllautca ti hcum os deppals tog kcab ruoy dna ,sretsis ruoy htiw noitceffa ni rehtegot debbur tog skaeB
.epolevne etihw nialp a
.dlohesuoh siht rof doog gnihtyna naem ylbissop t'ndluoc gninrom eht ni ylrae siht sukcur siht lla taht raelc yrev ti edam rettal eht hguoht neve
.niaga sgniw rieht daerps ot
egalliv eht ta lavitsef utpmorpmi na ta detarbelec osla erew tub
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.taehw nedlog fo edam
.noitpo taht evah t'ndid uoy tub
hguoht nialpxe did yeht tahW
,ecaps ni gniht hcus on saw ereht sa ,lios ehT
kaew dekool taht sgniw dna
snigiro eht tuoba yrots swen a ni denoitnem saw eman ruoy nehw
,esuac tsol a saw ti taht decnuonna dna
,dlrow eht fo tser eht elihw
.hcruhc llams eht ot slatrop gib eht fo tnorf ni demrof dworc gib a litnu ,teerts-
si yrots s’yadoT dna
:enigami dluoc uoy pmats elbissop yreve htiw detaroced
.evila drib tsetsaf eht saw eh taht revo dna revo gnivorp
.ylimaf ruoy dna uoy rof htob
,seye s'rehtaf eht dna
- sladem nedlog sih detneserp ssortabla nA
erofeb rettel a nettog reven dah uoY
sdniw gnitfilpu ,mraw dna seiks eulb sseldne fo smaerd uoy gnivig yb thgilf fo kcal eht rof pu ekam ot deirt dnim ruoy sa yldliw meht gnippalf
.dlrow siht fo emehcs dnarg eht ni
,eudrevo erew tuoba nettogrof dah uoy sllib emos taht dednimer gnieb fo raef lanoitarri eht tsniaga gnithgiF
,yaw eht no decudorp egaruotne ruoy rettalc duol dna deticxe eht sa llew sa
,rethgifeseehC yb ''sgniW deppilC“ saw sihT
,tew tog yeht sselnu sselthgiew tsomla yllausu
gnihtyreve gnitarbelec
,esicerp eb ot ,rO .elpoep htiw mirb eht ot dellif dna duol
,eye dekan eht ot elbisiv niamer dluow emoh hguoht nevE
,noom eht fo eseehc eht ylnO
tcelloc ot nwot eht detisiv laiciffo tnemnrevog a nehw niarb ruoy otni eson ruoy hguorht demmar baws a teg ot hguone evarb
.yawa thgir seye rieht morf yawa taolf t'ndid selbram yretaw esoht
,sgniht fo esruoc larutan eht ni pets
,sretsis ruoy dna
- eman a htiw ecaf hcae
enoyreve - sgnilbis regnuoy dna redlo ruoy dna
.tsrif yrtne ruoy ecnuonna ot emit eht uoy gnivig tuohtiw sllaw yloh eseht edisni desserp tog
ereht nwod drib rehto yreve dna hcae t'nsaW
.tsrif ta elpoep wef a ylno fo noitnetta eht thguac
sdrahcro fo seert eht ot gnidnet
.ycnega ecaps eht fo laes xaw eht dezingocer uoy nehw dnim ruoy dessorc ylno
:emitnaem eht ni meht ot klat ro ees ot elbanu dna
.wodniw eht fo ssalg dnuor ,kciht eht saw tih ot deganam uoy lla tey
,ytivarg fo pirg gnitnelernu eht tsniaga gnithgif
,yad elgnis a ylno ,tfel emit elttil os ylno saw erehT
naiva fo yrotsih eht ni thgilf tsegnol eht ni ekatrap
regnol tib a rof ti ni gniyats ton detterger uoy won tey
,uoy ekil nikpmub yrtnuoc a did woh dna yhw tuB
srebmem-werc wollef ruoy fo enoyreve tub
noitnem elbaronoh na sa dednemmocer saw yrots rieht ,secalp-muidop eht fo eno rof tuc eht ekam t’ndid yeht elihW
.meht fo tnorf ni gniklaw sgel regnuoy eht htiw pu peek ot ygrene eht meht nevig evah tsum ytisoiruc esohw
,lriws dliw a ni yb dehsur syad eht
.noziroh eht sdrawot dna
renetsil detaitininu eht rof tey ,thgilf koot uoy nehw
.mrahc dna amsirahc larutan rieht ot eud
yawa tpews tog ecnaraeppa degnahc yltaerg ruoy ot tcaer dluow ylimaf ruoy woh tuoba seirrow eht tuB
erutuf eht ni sraey llits saw tenalp siht morf erutraped laer ruoy taht semit elpitlum demialcorp uoy hguoht nevE
,elpoep fo retsulc siht fo tnorf eht ta ,uoy dnA
egatireh elbisivni rieht fo esuaceb laicepS
.sdrib fo rebmun detceles a yb ylno derimda ,sttellab cimsoc
nwot elohw eht gnirb ot deganam dah uoy ekil
devloser ylkciuq saw gnidnatsrednusim ehT
.sraey tsal eht ni decneirepxe dna nees dna denrael dah uoy sgniht eht lla yb derutparne dna
,dum kciht hguorht
:derettam evah dluow ti taht toN
,rood eht gnirewsna yllanigiro ecno eht
?ecalp tsrif eht ni esab-atad siht ni pu dne uoy did woH
depparw ylluferac
hcruhc eht ni rehtaf eht ot ti desserdda
egalliv ruoy ni eno ylno eht erew uoy ,kcab sraey wef a ,lleW
.srats eht neewteb yenruoj a no dnik-
.sdica-onima tnereffid fo
,tserof yrd a ni erif a ekil ylkciuq daerps ecnerrucco lausunu siht tuoba drow eht tuB
eno etirw ot deganam evah dluow uoy fi sdractsop ro srettel yna daer dluoc ydobon dna
,kaeb ykahs ylthgils a htiW
.ecnarongi ngineb htiw derongi tog snoitcejbo ruoy
neht dna nosrep tneserp hcae fo secaf eht otni dekool
?toidi emos ekil dnuora sbmil ruoy gnignilf uoy ta derats elpoep elihw tnemssarabme dna erutrot siht lla yhw dnA
,draob no smuidem egarots rehto eht lla ekilnu
gninnips ylwols os reve
,pu dewohs stnerapdnarg ruoy neve tib a retfa dnA
,noereht morf dnA   .ecapS
,eid yllanif dna ,dlo worg
,ydob a no gnillup ytivarg fo gnileef ehT :niaga
:snoitativni rieht dewollof dah taht elpoep rehto eht lla dna uoy deteerg eettimmoc a
,scimim sih ni edirp fo noisserpxe raelc a edih ot elbanu ,uoy ta
,sexelpmoc lairtsudni gnilwarps dna syawhgih daorb
dnuora nrut ot egru eht tsniaga gnithgif
:ekib a gnidir ekil t'nsaw gniklaw ekil demees ti sa
.egalliv ybraen eht sdrawot noissecorp gnol a ni hcram a detrats ylimaf elohw eht dna
hcruhc eht ta rehtaf yloh eht tlusnoc ot edam saw noisiced laretalinu na
- napsefil sti fo dne eht gniraen dna pu desu
,revo dna revo ,wena pihs taht no thguat dna denrael eb ot dah gnihtyreve ,siht eveihca oT
yllaciteneg rehto eht lla fo tuo dna
,stnemevom ruoy fo hcae tsniaga gnithgif sretaw ypmaws elbisivni eht
stnadnecsed ruoy wolla dluow
:gniniart emas eht hguorht og ot dah lla yeht dnA
.snomres sih gnirud erutpircs yloh eht morf naht
,ereh tsenoh eb ot
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tohs elgnis eno ni ylimaf elohw siht erutpac ot kcab raf
.swalc ruoy ni srepap fo eldnub siht otno nwod dekool uoY
werc eht fo rebmem eno tsael ta yb deipucco meht fo hcae
pihs a fo levram lacigolonhcet siht neve ton taht dna
uoy derrefsnart dna yb gnihsur emac esrun a
.dnim ruoy ni deifidilos yllanif seciohc ruoy fo secneuqesnoc eht dna
,niatruc kcalb-diov a fo tnorf ni anirellab a ekil
moor eht gnihtab dna
.revo dna revo moor eht ni esle enoyreve ot ecneserp ruoy gnimialcxe
,ti fo skool eht morf htob
stnerapdnarg rieht
,ycavirp ni ti nepo ot sriatspu moor a otni repap fo eceip elttil eht htiw epacse dluoc uoy erofeb dna
- snosaer rehto eht lla rof laiceps enoemos erew uoy ,niaga neht tuB
,retnec srotisiv eht deretne uoy nehw
,dehcaer neeb dah pihs siht fo noitanitsed lanif eht nehw
,etirw ro daer dluoc ylimaf ruoy ni esle ydoboN
,rethgifeseehC yb ”sgniW deppilC“
dekrow taht fo yna woh dootsrednu uoy taht toN
.hturt denrodanu eht tub gnihton saw yawa emit gnol a retfa emoh gnimoc tuoba uoy dlot yeht tahw tuo denrut tI
,senot dna semulov fo slevel lla ni gniprihc dna gnireehc nageb ylimaf ruoy dna uoy elihW
- emit tsal eno nwod kcab ylf ot esohc taht wef yrev eht fo eno erew uoy ,tluser a sA
,gnol oot rof seye rieht esolc ot derad esle ydobon dna
,elpoep esoht lla fo kcab eht ni ,yllanif dnA
seirots neddih eht ni detseretni yleniuneg erew daetsni dna
.nwo rieht no dnuorg eht morf pu seidob rieht tfil regnol on dluoc ohw seno dlo eht fo retteb eht nettog dah ytisoiruc tey
eht nihtiw deirrac ti egdelwonk eht
sllaw eht morf ohce ot deganam eciov gnimoob sih dna
:tfig gnitrap a sa uoy ot evig dluohs yeht tahw skeew rof derednop dah meht fo lla ,suhT
.meht fo enoyreve dna hcae htiw
:decudortni tog ohw dnuora lla secaf wen fo tol a dnA
tsehc ruoy no ylduorp rebmun-werc dna
,serutcip txetnoc fo tuo ,tnereffid fo detsisnoc ylno
.elbissop sa selpmas-AND esrevid ynam sa
dnoyeb rehtruf erutnev ot erised peed eht
.eno yhtlaeh a eb dluow gnirpsffo yreve taht erusne ot
,tnorfpu uoY :daetsni ereht klaw ot eerga lla uoy edam sredle eht
.gnola meht fo lla gnirb ot ecaps hguone ton ylpmis saw ereht sa
htrof no os dna ,meht retfa esoht dna ,meht retfa esoht dna ,nerdlihcdnarg ruoy ,skcihc nwo rieht dluow os dnA
,snoitasilivic lla fo egdelwonk fo yteritne eht gnidloh
- nomres gninrom s'yadot ot srelevart gnissap modnar emos neve dna
.noihsaf ylredro na ni sgel ruoy evom ot woh tegrof ot deganam yllufsseccus dah uoY
.ecaf sih no deraeppa elims dlim a litnu
ot htrib nevig dah tenalp emoh ruoy
.ecalp tsrif eht ni stluser yna dleiy
seye lufhctaw eht rednu lla
,yawa raf tenalp a morf drib mraf elttil a fo egatireh siht neht
,skcihc gnuoy eht llA
uoy htiw dioralop elttil eht gnirapmoc ylluferac elihw sworb sih gnisiar dna gnilwocs nageb
,yrtnuoc eht ssorca lla deilppa dah ohw setadidnac elpma
,sdnah ruoy htiw yawa meht oohs ot dah uoy
.emoc ot tuoba saw tahw rof htgnerts latnem dna
elpoep derehtag eht fo tser eht
.sruoy fo smeti esoht ni deirrac
.doof fo sniatnuom laretil dna
edis yreve dna esuoh yreve morf ni gninioj nageb srehto hguone noos dna
.noitidnoc gnikrow ni egayov-raey-dnasuoht siht evivrus ot dedeen taht
.sgel ruoy neewteb ni
,revird tneitapmi na fo
,sefiw wen dna sdnabsuh weN
esoht fo nuf ekam ot naht retteb wenk
nosaer rehto eht derebmemer yletaidemmi uoy dnA
.esol ylno dluoc uoy elttab a ni
,ecnelis eiree dna neddus a otni llef yliratnemom hcihw
:rebmem wollef a osla saw
,emoh s'remraf roop a morf dna
wenk uoy dlrow llams eht ,os dnA
rorrim weivraer eht ni knurhs ylwols
,laem yreve ta snoitpo artxe-artxe teg uoy did ylno ton oS
,ti ot tuo dehcaer uoy ,tcnitsni ni tsomlA
,yoj fo tuo gniyrc
,stnerapdnarg ruoy htiw gnidne dna
,noitarbelec gnihcnual dnarg a retfa yltrohS
."stenalp" dellac skcor gib eseht fo eno nees gnivah reven
sdrawretfa sretsis dna srehtorb redlo ruoy lla yb dewollof
,enod dna dias saw gnihtyreve retfa dnA
senizagam ecneics fo tuo erom gnidaer yb
gninrom lufetaf eno sa
,sekoj ta gnihgual
,delevart pihs eht rehtruf eht tluciffid erom dna erom teg dluow noitacinummoc fo tros yna taht dna
skeew wef tsrif eht ni dna ,ylraed dessim uoy gnihtemos saw thgilf-roodni rof moor fo kcal eht ylnO
ytisrevid eguh eht fo yalpsid duorp A
ydob elohw ruoy gard ot dah uoy ekil hcum yrev tlef spets ruoy fo hcae
,uoy ta sregnif gnitniop dna senac gniklaw no gninael
,teef s'eno dnoyeb lios eht fo hcuot eht
.egamulp etihw erup sih morf detcelfer tog taht thgil eht ni
skoob erom daer yldednah-elgnis uoy ,sraey eseht nI
skcocaep lufituaeb ro ,thgiew ydob nwo rieht semit ynam tfil ot elba gnieb ,selgae gnorts
gnihton tnaem flesruoy ebircsed ot sgniht esoht lla fi sA
ria eht otni srehtaef sih fo wef a gnidnes
!ylrae oot ruoh na taht lla dna
:dlrow siht fo gniliec eulb lanrete eht dnoyeb mlaer sseldne eht otni gniog erew uoY
,ytivarg orez fo gnileef eht ot demotsucca teg ot saw lla fo tsriF
tnatsid ylbanigaminu ylno fi neve
flesruoy ti ecneirepxe ot tub ,noitatneserp a ni ro erutcip a no thgis siht ees ot gniht eno saw tI
,erehpsomta eht hguorht senigne gniraor htiw debmilc ti sa enalp-ecaps eht fo elttab hsilleh eht evivrus ot ylno
semit elpitlum oS
sdrib rehto ot ssenesolc fo epyt siht decneirepxe gnivah
dnuora lla renniht tol A
:dworc derehtag eht ni noitcaer dexim a dekraps taht ecnetnes A  ."!snevaeh eht
,sraey ni ton derusaem
rettel rieht ni ti dellac yeht tahw s'taht - trop ecaps eht ta gnivirrA
.traeh ruoy ot ylthgit koob-erutcip dlo taht gnulc uoy ,elihwnaeM
gniganam osla elihw dnuorg eht revo teef ruoy gniggard
evil yadyreve eht ni elbacilppa ro yrassecen mrof ro yaw yna ni saw ti tuoba gnihton sa
,rehtona ro yaw emos ni
,snoitome fo murtceps etelpmoc eht
.deppilc neeb dah yeht fi sa tsomla ,etalucsame dna
ecaps eht ta deretnuocne tsrif uoy srotcod dna sledom esoht lla tahT
.srebmemwerc sdnasuoht elpitlum fo tuo nezod a naht ssel
,lla ta "laitnesse" ro "cisab" leef t'ndiD
- edam uoy stnemevom fo dnik tahw rof hcterts raf a saw "gniklaw" mret eht
,erew uoy drib eht eciwt tsomla won meht fo lla
.erofeb enod reve dah esle enoyna naht
,elttirb ydaerla saw lairetam eht dnA .sseldeeN
:tenalp eht fo llew-ytivarg eht deretne enalp eht ecno yhw
,srosseforP dna srotcoD
derebmemer uoy ycnega tnemnrevog a fo laes xaw eht dna ,"!dneb ton oD"
,tneserp enoyreve fo sllac dna sprihc gnigaruocne tsal eht ot gninetsil
.koot uoy htaerb deniarts hcae htiw tsehc ruoy tsniaga kcab gnihsup neve dna
,"deilf-maerd" uoy sa
thgilf tsrif rieht no sdrib-ybab ekil deticxe tog ylneddus
.snoitareneg ni tub
.riahcleehw a otni spirg mrif htiw
...sselemoh ,sresserdriah
.tnemnorivne lausunu siht ot
noitarimda hsidlihc htiw was uoy sthgis nwonknu eht lla
.tuoba elttil ylno
.hcrop tnorf eht no thgin eht hguorht depmac dah ylimaf elohw eht
deniamer taht syad wef eht desu uoY
yenruoj a no derettam sgniht esoht fo enon esuaceB
,kcolf elohw ruoy fo noissecorp siht
.tseirp eht fo eciov gnidnuos duorp dna
elbat sti ffo dehsup tog ylraen ti emit eno taht tuoba dnA
:noisnetxe ni dnA
.emoh ruoy fo uoy dnimer dluohs ti dna
uoy del yletamitlu tahw ni ekatrap ot pu dengis dah uoy tahT
.ti detcepxe reven uoY
,stnerap ruoy yb sretcarahc nevenu dna ykahs ni nettirw ,rettel a dna
,ylevitarugif dna yllaretil ,eulb eht fo tuo yletelpmoc emac tI
.llew sa os od yam dlrow wen eht tahT :hsiw terces reh
sruoh eht tneps ylimaf ruoy dna uoy ,daetsnI
seiks remmus raelc latsyrc eht morf dednecsed noegip regnessem a
,stnerap rieht yb meht ot nevig
,htrae no ereh llits erew uoy sa gnol sa dna
.emit eerf ruoy ni koob a otni slirtson ruoy kcits ot regae ro
.meht htiw secneirepxe 'stnerap ruoy deredisnoc uoy fi swenk doog tnaem reven yeht dna
redluohs ruoy no dnah sih decalp eH
;ylf ot woh uoy thguat dah taht koob s'nerdlihc desu ylivaeh
ecin eb dluow ti teY
,dad ruoy dna mom ruoy
,sdleif eht ni tuo
.yrots denoitnemerofa eht htiw
.tey tsuj meht nepo ot dewolla t'nerew uoy tuB
:dnatsrednu ot gniniart dna noitacude fo sraey eerht uoy koot taht snosaer
rehtona ylno saw eno siht taht dna
pihs taht otno tog ohw ydoboN
.flesruoy yenruoj siht fo dne eht ees t'ndluow uoY
:seitivitca fo kcal a tuoba nialpmoc t'ndluoc uoy dna gniw a fo palf eht ni yb tnew sraey owt esohT
,nwot larur llams eht ni gnivirrA
,tsehc sih ni tekcop a morf erutcip a decudorp drib eht ,ereht lavirra ruoy retfA
,pu worg dluow skcihc ruoy dnA
taes ruoy fo tuo flesruoy hsup ot htgnerts eht pu retsum dluoc uoy erofeb dna
.ekil tlef ytivarg woh nettogrof dah ydob ruoy
.sehctarcs-nekcihc ekil kool sdrow eht gnikam tuohtiw
:seybdoog rieht yas ot elbanu dna traped uoy gniees no tuo ssim ot diarfa
,epacse uoy tel gnilliwnu denrut ylneddus dah taht
.ot htrib nevig dah ehs nerdlihc eht lla fo
.dnim dna seye ruoy fo ffo liev a deppir
noitceffa dna evol fo serutseg dna seitilamrof tsal eht egnahcxe
stnadnecsed ruoy tahT
sruovaedne ralimis nekatrednu ydaerla dah sdrib taht lobmys A
,tneitap-recnac a ekil riahc-leehw a ni dehsup gnieb uoy yb
meht derebmemer uoy fi wonk ot regae llits meht fo hcae tub ,eromyna gnuoy os ton won
,oga gnol emit a morf
,stsigolohcysp ro stsitneics gniwonk lla ylgnimees eht neve ton ,ydoboN
,sliame ro senohp hguorht seno devol rieht dellac ylraluger srehtO
,pihs siht no ,ereH
emoc won dah emit eht taht langis ot ecnayonna gnisaercni htiw hctaw-tsirw sih no gnippit
,denibmoc srotsecna ruoy fo lla naht
deirrac taht seno eht dnif ot saw detnaw yeht llA
egaugnal gnidnuos ythgim dna hgih eht rehpiced ot gniyrt pu evag ylkciuq uoy ,ylsuogolanA
.esle gnihtyna od ro stobor dliub ro
,seye sih ni tnilg krad a htiw denraw eh ,teY
:lepahc elttil siht ni
ylimaf ruoy ot seybdoog lanif ruoy yas ot ecnahc tsal ruoy tog uoy
.sutarappa eht dnuora gniretsulc
.ylkciuq sa raeppasid ot ylno
,ygrene tuohtiw dna llud yllausu
.gnireenigne ro scisyhp ro scitamehtam ni seerged rieht dna slwo trams deen t'ndid yehT
,htiw AND ruoy derahs uoy elpoep eht lla fo esuaceb ,kcul dnA
.ecno gnidnal reve tuohtiw tenalp eht etagivanmucric ot deganam dah eh taht gnivorp
.rac sih fo wor taes kcab eht otni flesruoy sa llew sa
- stnerap ruoy htiw yoj fo sraet dehs wef a neve dna
,stfig gnitrap ruoy erew yehT
,ytiralupop dna emaf rieht ot eud dworc eht fo tuo doots ylpmis trop-
,sraey eerht naht erom rof emoh morf enog gnieb retfa ,won tuB
,deb a erahs ot dah uoy nehw gnineve yreve
:uoy erew snoisseforp dna elpoep fo yteirav gib siht gnoma dnA
,ylkciuq fo dnik ti ot desu tog uoy ,ylgnisirpruS
emit tsrif eht rof decneirepxe eb ot dah gnihtyreve ,sdrawretfa dnA
.gnitirw fo elyts lausunu eht ot eud
,ni uoy tup yeht riahcleehw diputs taht fo tuo erew uoy esuaceb ylno
,dereves enil-evil tsal eht
,seitic gib sti htiw
,tnemom yrev taht ni uoy htiw thguoht emas eht derahs evah tsum rebmem-werc rehto yreve ,ti fo skool eht morf
sraey rof enog eb dluow uoY
wena noitasilivic a tratser ot elba neve erew
,srehtorb ruoy erew ereht ,nehT
tpada ot ytiliba fo kcal rieht dna
.eno lanif eht eb dluow ti hguoht neve
,egamulp hguorht gninnur dniw eht
,peels t'ndluoc uoY
ythgim eht yb edistuo deirrac tog taht sdrow eht no ni netsil ot etarepsed
deen t'ndid yehT
sporc tnalp ot woh wenk ohw sdrib deen t'ndid yehT
yliratnulov tuo deppord rehtie setadidnac eht fo retrauq doog a dna
,ereht klaw ot esohc uoy ,ylimaf ruoy teem ot yaw ruoy edam uoy nehw teY
siht denrut tnemecnuonna ralucatceps taht retfA
srekoolno erem fo detsisnoc demussa dah uoy dworc taht fo nosrep rehto yreve dna hcae teY
,oga sraey devirra taht rettel a fo esuaceB
detacilpmoc os gnihtemos nialpxe ot tpmetta yna dluow ron
.sguh rieht ni luferac erom dna srehtorb ruoy naht etats eligarf ruoy fo erawa erom
yadot esuaceb dna
,skcihc elttil eht dna
tisiv ot detivni tog
.ti tuoba uoy hcaet ot derehtob enoyna taht ro
,yltnelis dedda neh eht ,dnA
.tneserp sesrun dna srotcod eht fo tsetorp eht rednu neve
segap gnidaf won ,lufruoloc ecno
,elddim ruo morf ,gnilegdelf elttil sihT"
.rezilauqe taerg eht ylf-tuo dluoc
.tniop emos ta yletelpmoc esaec ylekil dluow ti litnu
,ti wenk uoy erofeB
,rettel elgnis a etorw ylno uoY
,reisae dna retsaf neeb evah dluow ereht gniylF
,dlrow dna tnenitnoc
.yadot litnu sraey fo snoillim rof deruobrah dna
.esrevinu eht fo diov krad eht otni wodniw eht tuo erats dna yldi dnuora tis ylpmis ot shtnom dna syad ynam oot saw taht dna
.rettel eht morf swen lufrednow eht decnuonna dah tseirp eht yad eht no sa uoy fo duorp sa
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.esimed erutuf ruoy demialcorp dah eh ekil dednuos evah tsum ti
:syawyna kcay-ytekcay lacinhcet taht fo lla tegrof uoy edam evah dluow
enalp eht otno kcab pets neht dluoc uoy fi erus regnol on erew ylneddus uoy sa
.drager taht ni gnittif yrev saw "pihS-noitareneG" eman eht ,lleW
.tenalp eht morf yawa enalp eht dellup taht etilletas a no kooh gnitator fo tros emos
samajyp ytrid ruoy gniraew
.egaugnal ,htlaew ,gnignirbpu ,erutluc
napsemit a ekat dluow taht
eman ruoy gniraeb
.nees reve dah uoy naht
,dlo na ;ylbmurc dna yrd
gab foorp-dniw dna -rehtaew sih ni gniyrrac
- "kooh-yks" a dellac yeht gnihtemos htiw dekcod ti litnu
dna dnuora dehsad yeht elihw
ecnecseloda deretne gnivah ylerab
,uoy htiw sgnignoleb wef yrev ylno gnirb ot dewolla erew uoy taht denrael yeht woh dnA
ylkciuq yrev deciton uoy ,retnec gniniart eht ta skeew wef a retfA
setammoor ruoy deppals ylraluger uoy
,lleW .lwo citamhtsa dlo emos ekil gniffup dna
fi owt ro raet a dehs evah dluow emos ylerus dna
,ebolg eht dnuora lla dnik-naiva fo lla yb dehctaw ylekil
demees ti yhw ot sa worbeye desiar a tuohtiw ton tiebla ,esuoh sih ot uoy democlew
,emit emos koot tseirp ehT .s'!tssP dna
detareggaxe yltaerg rehtie saw ecneirepxe siht taht demussa dah uoy yllaitinI
.meht laever ot emoc ton dah emit reporp eht
,dworc eht otni ylduol demialcorp eh "!nerdlihc yM"
,sdik rof koob erutcip eht dnA
,uoy dnuora lla werg
,esicerp erom eb ot ro ,uoY
,"liaM ytiroirP hgiH" ,"laitnedifnoC"
.ecarbme gnihsurc enob a otni uoy dellup won dna
enog neeb dah uoy ecnis yad elgnis eno ton dega gnivah
,retnec srotisiv eht ot yawllah siht nwod gniklaw
,mra ruoy fo hcaer nihtiw fi sa tsomla deraeppa ti sa
.epolevne etihw eht
.htaed ruoy erofeb ylimaf ruoy ees ot tog uoy ecnahc tsal eht eb dluow
.uoy dnuora sedis lla morf gniprihc yrgna fo tol a gnikraps
ti ta delliks yrev uoy erew rehtien tub
,"!nosrep desserdda eht ot ylno revileD"
,mraf ruoy morf lios eht htiw dellif raj a erew
:staoc bal etihw ,gnol rieht ni stsitneics eht fo eno ksa ot tog uoy ecno gniyfsitasnu saw ti sa ysae sa saw rewsna ehT ?siht otni tog
.tneserp ydob fo epahs dna ega yreve
,sdrocer deeps ynam sih dewohs noclaf A
sebor yltseirp kcalb a ni evod dlo na ,rehtaf yloh ehT
1202 tsetnoC yrotS gnirpS s’reehS ta tubed rieht edam ohw
citegrene sa ssel tib eno ton dna
,esuohmraf s'ylimaf ruoy fo hcrop tnorf eht otno
tibro ralucric sti morf detraped pihs eht
.elbacilppa noN .sselesu saw
niaga reve gnihtyna tae ot teg reven dluow uoy
.drib mraf elttil A
,deveihca reve dah ylimaf ruoy ni enoyna
.ecalp tsrif eht ni elbaiv yllaicnanif levart-ecaps edam dah taht ygolonhcet ehT
tnemamrif eulb sseldne eht otni kcab gnisir
,erew yeht sa nialp dna elpmis ,sgniht esehT
,revo dna revo ,tfel ot thgir morf depmuj yeht sa rettel ruoy rehpiced ot stnemom wef a koot ylno
:eno ekil dekool ylerus uoy taht demrifnoc rorrim a otni ezag kciuq a hguoht neve
- snisiar fo stnuoma suoipoc htiw laemtao
.dessap dah sruoh wef a ylno ekil mees ti edam
,slatrop eht edistuo dnats ot dah elpoep litnu neve semitemos dna yad yreve mirb eht ot dellif saw hcruhc elttil eht
- tsafkaerb raluger ruoy fo seceip gniniamer yna fo denaelc
.stnemom wef a retfa kcab peerc ylwols ot meht rof ylno
,kaeb eht no nus a fo htmraw dlim eht
guh tsal a ,yllaniF
erutcip a dewohs neh nialp a dnA
,seno elttil eht sa
.ereht nrob saw taht noitareneg wen hcae rof
,dad ruoy dna mom ruoY
eht ekam ot hctarcs morf pu edam thgirnwod ro
?dne eht litnu evivrus osla ti dluow tey
- sselehtenon gniticxe deyats emoh gnivael tey
.ylimaf ruoy ot noitativni eht yaler dluow eh taht depoh dna
.lacitirc noissim ro laitnesse saw taht enoemos t'nerew uoy ,dne eht nI
detniat eb ot seiromem tsal eht tnaw t'ndid uoY
.ycnega-ecaps eht fo ogol eht rednu
hpargotohp eht ni derutpac saw tahw tuo ekam yldrah dluoc eno taht ynam oS
,daor ytsud eht fo trid eht tsniaga ti tcetorp ot tsehc ruoy ot ylthgit pils etihw eht gnidloh
,stnerapdnarg ruoy lla dnA
revo dednah yllanif dna gniod saw eh revetahw htiw deifsitas demees eh litnu
,sdrow tsal eht yas ot stnemom fo tnuoma etairporppa eht koot uoy
,hgih erew snoisnet dna snoissergga
.dlrow wen a no hctarcs morf
,scipot fo dleif daorb a ni egdelwonk dessama
:egayov nediam sti no ffo koot neve ti erofeb pihs siht ni sraey owt dneps ot dah uoy yhw saw
erom ton saw gnitraP
taht seiromem ni gnitluser
uoy dessim dah flesti htrae fi sa tsomlA
:yadot ereh emoc dah enoyrevE .elpoep ruoy
,kcen ruoy ni revird tneitapmi yna tuohtiw ,teY
.sevreser-taf ruoy ffo evil ot dah uoy taht dna
,meht erofeb emac taht enoyreve dna
.neppah ot gniog saw retsinis ro ekila gnihton ,daetsni ,nehW