.rehtnap kcalb llat eht tsniaga spih reh degdun yllufyalp iaM
yrahcaZ morf tuo dils eh ,dehsinif ecnO
,mih dessik dna delggig ehS
.enilef eht rof muc fo sesod wef tsal sih evag dna
.noitcaer s'enilef kcalb eht degduj dna detset eh
",mih htiw pihsnoitaler ym fo tnetxe eht fo erawanu era stnerap ym sesoprup dna stnetni lla rof …dnA
,erofeb flesym deregnif ev'I
"?esle gnihtemos yrt llits nac eW
.niaga deksa ramO
moor mrod yzoc eht edisni elttes ot nugeb dah esle enoyrevE
.sotohp lareves htiw segassem sih ot deilper dah kcaM dneirfyob sih taht was eH
.enilef llat eht ecarbme dna guh ot dniheb morf emoc ramO tlef yrahcaZ
.taews dna ksum htiw yvaeh saw moor eht
,ssik peed a rof esolc selzzum rieht thguorb ehS
.htrof dna kcab depmup epoletna eht sa
.aera nwotnwod eht fo tuo yaw rieht edam yeht elihw
.hcamots dna tsehc sih ssorca detrad taht
,esion elbissop rof nrecnoc elttil saw ereht dnA
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,dnim t'ndluow I"  .dekniw ramO ",dnuor erom eno og dluoc uoy smeeS ?nuf emos evah ew fi thgirla eb ti dluoW"
.sknalb wef tsal sti tohs htgnel s'yrahcaZ fo pit eht litnu detiaw eH
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.mih evol dna erac yleniuneg dluow elpoep ynam os taht
,sih gnola spal yltfos eugnot enilef s’raugaj ehT
,dnah s’kcaM koohs dna
.moor mrod llams sih ot noitidda tnellecxe na rof ekam dluow yeht wenk eh
,hcnul rieht retfA
seirots trohs gnillepmoc etaerc ot yaw a sa gnitirw sesu ohw
.dias iaM ",hcum os uoy dessim ev'I ,yrahcaZ"
2 fo 2 traP ,sivaD suiraD yb
"!oot uoy dessim ev'I …iaM"
.stsaerb ruf klis mrif reh otni ecaf sih deirub eh elihw
!nuf fo ytnelp gnivah era eerht uoy epoH"
ssik a meht fo htob evig ot revo delwarc iaM
iaM ot revo dekool neht enilef llat ehT
kcaM ot evig ot slaem tuo-ekat emos pu dekcip yrahcaZ
yad artxe na rof moor mrod sih ni deyats elpuoc eht fi si
.keehc s'yrahcaZ debbur ramO "?hcum ooT"
,draeh htob uoy ekil llew
.gnihtyreve rof deraperp evah ot demees ev’uoy ,sknahT“
.iaM htiw saw I ekil uoy htiw hguor eb t'now I ,yrrow t'noD"
.tey tsuj meht htiw xes fo cipot eht hcaerb ot tnaw t’ndid eH
.stfig dnuof wen sih fo lla
sdnah rieht fo htob koohs kcaM
.resolc denael
.htolchsaw a htiw nwod flesmih deppihw eh elihw deddon dna dehsulb yrahcaZ
,yrahcaZ rof gnol os neeb dah tI
stcejorp gnitirw
.denialpxe yrahcaZ
,dehsulf elzzum s’yrahcaZ  .deksa iaM
,sivaD suiraD yb ”syaD egelloC“
.deeps eht esaercni ot spih sih dekcub epoletna ehT  .desaet ramO
,desolc erew swodniw eht deciton tsuj eh hguohT
sdileye sih otni kcab dellor eye s'enilef ehT
”,ecalp eht no eye na gnipeek rof sknahT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
"?elpoep rehto gniees uoy fo stcepsorp eht tuoba tnatiseh eh saW
.eciov ykahs a htiw dias yrahcaZ
!yad lla ereh ni yats uoy gnikam rof yrroS“
.deyaws liat
",did I dalg os m'I dnA
”,flesym siht ot wen llits
s'iaM "!taerG"  .dias ramO
.ecnartne s’enilef eht tsniaga flesmih denil ramO sa tuo daerps erew sgel rednels gnol siH
,pohs llams eht tfel yeht nehW
neercs eht dekcolnu yrahcaZ
,stnemom wef a nihtiW
.trofmocsid rojam tuohtiw sregnif s'ramO fo wef a ekat dluoc eh taht desirprus tib a saw yrahcaZ
ramO "?tsrif ruoy eb dluoc I
.detseuqer sa yrahcaZ otni egnulp ylluf t'ndid llits eH
"?yttik ytterp ym ,flesruoy yojnE"
,spil sih dekcep ramO
.ebul fo elttob llams eht mih dednah dna deddon yrahcaZ
.emahs a hcus ,wA"
,meht eviecer ot nihc sih detfil yrahcaZ
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
".ecap ruoy ta og lliw I
edis sih no dial ramO
stnalp dettop eht desahcrup iaM ,desimorp sa dnA
htgnel sih fo esab eht debbarg eH
.msagro rieht ot esolc dehcaer dah owt eht sa ediskcab s'ramO nwod deggard
.ezeens yvaeh a tuo tel ylneddus ramO sa ffo detfird
.lios hserf fo gab llams a dna
seman tsal ruo fo esuaceb noitatneiro ni pu deriap tog eW“
esolc ni dellup rehtnap kcalb ehT
.iaM dna ramO htiw etad sih erofeb ecivda dnuos emos yrahcaZ dneirfyob sih evag kcaM ,emit tsaL
.oot mih rof sgnileef thguac osla I
taht ekil uoY"  .rae s’yrahcaZ otni repsihw ot esolc ni denael epoletna ehT
tuo dehcaer ramO  .stnalp sih fo tser eht dekcehc rehtnap kcalb eht sa
sredluohs sih otno sgel s'enilef eht tsioh ot dedeecorp dna deddon ramO  .dias yrahcaZ
.syad wef a nihtiw moolb dluow tub
,mih otni edils ylluf t'ndluoc eh hguoht nevE
.retaw delttob htiw detser owt eht elihw
,setunim wef a ni pu emoc lla dluow yeht wonk mih tel ot txet a kcaM tnes rehtnap kcalb ehT
notuf eht morf tuo debmilc ylluferac raugaj eht
.ria eht ni nwod dna pu sbob htgnel s'yrahcaZ sa
”,gnihtyna deen owt uoy fi wonk em tel dna elbatrofmoc teg ot eerf leef hguohT
”?oot daorba gniyduts uoy erA“
tup ot yltcaxe erehw si
.eunitnoc ot dedeecorp dna deddon ramO  .deffuh yrahcaZ
.spih sih dekcub dna
.pot a fo erom gnieb sdrawot nael ot dnet I
,dehsulb yrahcaZ  .deksa ramO
.detaslup dna llat doots htgnel s'yrahcaZ
deddon ramO dna iaM
.mottob ot em deksa reve sah eno on tsuj …yako s'tI"
.moolb ni erew taht steloiV nacirfA
efil sih fo tniop eht ta eb dluow eh taht denigami reven yrahcaZ
,seye s'rehtnap kcalb eht derutpac elprup fo sedahs yteirav tnereffid ehT
.yrahcaZ fo pot no debmilc iaM sa dehctaw dna
.htgnel eritne sih depolevne yletelpmoc ehs
troppus lanoitome dna evol dnuof wen sih elihW
,elbadnatsrednU"
spih s'iaM otno dehctal ylthgit sdnah s’rehtnap kcalb ehT
,spih reh pu detfil yltneg raugaj ehT
.noitanitsed eht dehcaer yeht ecno moor mrod sih ot stfig eht yrrac mih pleh yeht detsisni osla ramO dna iaM .nades cirtcele s'ramO ot kcab dedaeh oirt eht sa
.enoyreve rof ecneirepxe wen a eb dluow ti wenk eH
!rehtegot seiromem fo stol ekaM
ijome traeh a htiw kcab deilper eh
.yad eht fo tser eht rof od ot dennalp dah yeht tahw tuoba seton latnem koot yrahcaZ
!reippah eb t’ndluoc I dna setats eht ni ereh yats ym tuohguorht em depleh sah Z
spil eht no ssik reporp a iaM evig ot denrut neht yrahcaZ
,detcurtsni yrahcaZ ekil yltcaxe stnalp eht gniretaw eulB naissuR eht dewohs hcihw fo wef A
,sselhtaerb erew meht fo htoB
?ekil uoy gnihtemos ees ydaerlA"
.ni delttes eerht eht sa
.stnap s'yrahcaZ eveirter ot notuf eht fo edis sih ot txen roolf eht no revo dehcaer ramO
ytisrevinu hsinif I nehw yrtnuoc emoh ym ot kcab gnivom eb ll'I ecnis erugif I
",taht hctac etiuq t'ndid I
,rehtnap kcalb eht ediseb pu deklaw ramO
.mih htiw tpels reve t’ndah iaM dna
.mih pirts ot dekrow owt eht sa
yawa stfig eht lla tup ot dediced yrahcaZ
.srebmun enohp dna aidem laicos s'rehto hcae degnahcxe oirt eht sa
",esu nac uoy ebul emos tog I
,kaeps ot deirt eh revenehW
won htiw laed ot nrecnoc niam ehT
noitasrevnoc eht no deppordsevae llits srae enilef siH
.stsaerb reh deldnof yltneg dna
.nus eht fo ecafrus eht naht rettoh emoceb dah ecaf s'yrahcaZ
,dereviuq spil s'yrahcaZ
"?tseretni tseb sih rof tuo kool dna Z fo erac doog ekat lliw owt uoy taht tsurt I
"?oot stnalpesuoh fo erac ekat uoY"  .dias ramO
.pu sgel sih fo htob detsioh dna
!llew gniod era owt uoy raeh ot doog s’tI“
”?gnilttes neeb uoy evah woH
,yrahcaZ edisni deltsen htgnel s'ramO fo flah ecnO
sllaw lanigav kcils s'iaM otni flesmih dils eh
!elbuort on saw tI“
deldduc oirt eht sa
,ruf s'rehtnap kcalb htaenrednu niks eht ees dluoc epoletna eht fI
",won litnu detsal evah dluow uoy fo htob eht htiw pihsnoitaler ecnatsid-gnol ym fi deirrow tib a saw eh
;deddon iaM  .derepsihw ramO
,sivaD suiraD yb ”syaD egelloC“
s'iaM "!ytterp repus er'yehT
",tnaw uoy fi tsrif og nac uoy tub
,weiv otni emac iaM dna ramO nehW
.yadot rof sesolc gnihtyreve erofeb nur ot deen I sdnarre wef a evah I
”!sdneirf enif rehto sah eh taht wonk ot ecin s’tI
.rufdaeh srehtnap kcalb eht otni dedilg yllufyalp swalc reh
.mra sih debbur kcaM
.ijome kniw a htiw desaet kcaM
;denepo seye s'yrahcaZ
”,yadot rof su gnisuoh uoy etaicerppa tsuj eW
.nellop htiw yffuts tib a saw moor eht taht deciton dna ria eht deffins enilef egral ehT
",serutcip emos ekat ot diarfa eb t'nod dnA
.sgab gnippohs eht otno dleh eh elihw
dna shtnom wef a rof tuo gnah ot detrats ew ,elihw a retfA
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa reeuq kcalb a
ssik llams eht denruter yrahcaZ
.yrahcaZ rof daeha dial taht snwonknu ynam llits erew erehT .yad yb yad
.mih edisni peek ot ni htgnel eritne sih llup ot deirt dah yrahcaZ hguoht sa tlef ti
”?tnaw uoy fi dehtolc yats nac eW
.syob owt reh fo thgis eht ta delims raugaj ehT
,gnideerb lluf a rof evitisnes oot llits saw etatsorp s'enilef eht elihw taht denrael ramO
"?retal sotohp emos ekat ll'ew ebyaM" ,derepsihw dna
",uoy retfa ni og ll'I"  .dias iaM
.sreh otno dleh yltneg dna deddon eH
”.koob raey eht ni ti gnidaer rebmemer I
.gnissik htooms s'epoletna eht yb delffum erew snaom sih
.dedlof srae yrahcaZ
,tnaw uoy fi …ees I"
.resolc dehcni msagro sih sa ylpeed detnurg dna detnap ramO
,raugaj eht revo derewot ramO elihw kcab reh no dial iaM
nrecnoc yramirp siH
.ecalp dnoces ni derutaef saw ti sa meop taht rof skram hgih deviecer t'ndah eh
sllaw lanigav mraw reh
eno siht piks esaelp
egnulp eht koot epoletna eht
.lla ti dias elims s'ramO
.thgin eht rof elbatrofmoc dna deniatretne owt eht peek ot saw
.deb notuf dedlofnu eht rof
”.sotnaS iaM rentrap ym si siht dna rahsaB ramO m’I .uoy teem ot erusaelP“
,setunim wef a nihtiW
thguoht fo niart s'rehtnap kcalb ehT  .delims yrahcaZ
,denaorg ylduol dna
...kaerb gnirpS rof esuoh eht fo tuo em werht rehtaf ym revenehW"
"?ot em detnaw …uoY !hO"
!yletal retteb hcum gnioD“
.peels ot enohp sih tup dna
.yad a naht erom rof ecalp s'Z ta revo yats I nehw ti ekil t'nod ereh ytlucaf eht ,sulP
.dnah reh otno dleh ylthgit sregnif sih
pu spih sih detfil yrahcaZ sa dehctaw ramO
"…semoc emit eht nehw mih ssim yllaer annog m'I
,yrahcaZ edisni eb ot dellirht saw eH
,erew srovaedne erutuf sih tahw wonk reven yam eh fi nevE .ramO dna ,iaM
.edisni nellop ssecxe eht deppart hcihw
.deremmats yrahcaZ
dneirfyob reh htiw pu tis ot iaM dewolla eH
.sessik etanoissap rieht morf deniatnoc eb ylerab dluoc sraor dna snaom siH
,deb sih rednu tnew dna iaM morf guh eht desaeler yltneg yrahcaZ
.moor mrod sih ot pu stfig sih yrrac yrahcaZ depleh dna
,kcils dna mraw ylemertxe emoceb sllaw s'iaM
.seye sih desolc dna deddon yrahcaZ
,ydob reh fo hcni yreve wenk eh hguoht sa saw tI
?era uoy ti ekat I tub ,esac eht t’nsi tahT“ ,delkcuhc ramO
.revo yats em tel dluow rehtomdnarg ym
",taht evol dluow eh erus m'I“  .deilper ramO
.ramO ot revo enicidem ygrella fo selttob wef a dessot eh
".em rof tol a eb thgim tI
,reh ot pu dekool dna deddon eH
.ylteews dias ehS
.rucco reve dluow taht ylekilnu ylhgih demees ti ,llitS
.dnah sih otno sdloh iaM
,erutats retrohs sih etipseD
.tahc puorg rieht otni detivni saw kcaM taht mih demrofni hcihw
?tnaw uoy fi thginot ereh yats ot emoclew naht erom er'uoy
.pu dekrep deliat eulB naissuR eht
yrahcaZ dessik yltfos ramO
.tsrif ta stsurht wollahs evag dna
.gnineve eht fo redniamer eht rof seivom dehctaw dna
.mih ot pu dekool dna
.rewohs roodni llams eht rof dedaeh dna
.degnahcxe erew sdrow elttil
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
ecap thgir eht ta yllacitamotua krow spih s'ramO
,doohnam s'yrahcaZ tsniaga flesreh dednirg raugaj enilef ehT
.yrahcaZ guh ot revo tnew eh erofeb evaw mraw a meht evag kcaM
.ecaf sih no deyalpsid nirg yls a htiw ramO was dna revo dekool rehtnap kcalb ehT
,tsrif ym eb uoy tel ot yppah m'I"
.pihsnoitaler nepo na dereffo syug ruoy erofeb saw ti dnA
xaler ot detrats taoc ruf kcalb sih fo sdne ehT
.yrahcaZ ot txen tas eh erofeb hgis yvaeh a tuo tel ramO
,yldettimda hguohT
,rehtnap kcalb eht roF
,gnip enohp sih raeh dluoc yrahcaZ
".uoy fo htob eht no neeb ev'tsum ti drah woh enigami t'nac I"
.stcnitsni sih otni evig saw od dluoc eh llA
.tnaruatser ybraen a ta ihsus emos teg dna
?suovren tib a ,wA“
".drow ruo evah uoY
sfeirb rexob etihw sih ot nwod flesmih dnuof rehtnap kcalb ehT
.dees sih htiw stsaerb dna hcamots reh detniap dna
.rehtnap kcalb eht ta dekniw ramO
enilef llams eht dnuora dedlof ylthgils smra sih ,dias yrahcaZ
.kaeps ot deganam yllanif eH
dexaler ylluf dah sllaw lana eritne s'yrahcaZ ,sdrowretfA
mih erofeb doots namow gnuoy eht ,won teY
.niaga mih gniees ot drawrof kool I llew
.yrahcaZ desserdda ehs erofeb
.mih ssik ot sih ot denrut ecaf reh
.etsat neteews ylthgils reh dna
iaM dniheb morf revo delwarc eH
.spil s'yrahcaZ otno sessik mrif detnalp dna nwod denael ramO
.sevitcepsrep wen ot sredaer nepo dna
"?thgirla gnihtyrevE" ,delkcuhc ramO
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
”yaD egelloC“   yojne esaelP
.yalpsid lluf no saw ydob ralucsum dna nael s’epoletna eht
"?hsiw uoy fi rebmun ym owt uoy evig llits nac I
.em rof evol sih dessefnoc retal eh
.ramO dna iaM morf yalpsid eht morf denetfos t'ndah lasuora nwo siH
,kaeps ot deirt eh hcum woh rettam oN
deb eht no nwod sgel s'enilef eht delttes yltneg dna
,detarbiv enohp sih nehW
.reh htaeneb deyaws liat reh htiw ,yllufyalp deraor ehS
!rehtegot era owt uoy yhw ees nac I
,selggig iaM  .dias kcaM
.ylbatrofmoc mih edisni edils htgnel eritne sih tlef ylneddus ramO nehw
.spil s’yrahcaZ no ssik a detnalp dna pu daeh reh denael ehS
.msagro eerf sdnah tsrif sih dah eh elihw
!rebmemer I ,haey hO" ,deglub seye s'iaM
.dednopser yrahcaZ
dees fo sdnarts egral desaeler ylneddus htgnel s'enilef eht
yliratnemom deppots dna
kniw a yrahcaZ evig ot pu dekool epoletna yls ehT
elddim eht ni yrahcaZ dehciwdnas dah ramO dna iaM
.noisses eht emuser dna
…esuaceb ti gnittimda retfa tespu saw eh tuB
sehtolc lamrof thgit s'ramO htaenrednu taht was eH
ciffart og dna pots ni tas rac eht sa ffo dezod ylpmis rehtnap kcalb ehT
”…erus …haeY“  .deksa ramO
dedaeh lla oirt eht sa
,dewollaws yrahcaZ
od ot dah eh lla teY
,yresrun tnalp llams eht otni deretne oirt eht nehW
.rehtnap kcalb eht fo pot no debmilc eh erofeb
.elpoep rehto gnitad otni kool dluoc eh taht
,ruf kcen tfos s'ramO otni ecaf sih deltsen dna
,flesmih tsujda ot dedeen eh nehw morf
ijome traeh a tnes dna txet ni sknaht sih mih evag yrahcaZ
,skoob raey tsap sih morf yltcerroc sevres yromem fI
"?yrahcaZ htiw emit tsrif ruoy saw woH"
.deffuh ramO ",tihs hO"
.seiduts sih htiw dehsinif s’eh ecno emoh kcab gnivom eb ll'eh
ecap sih pu tpek epoletna ehT
.klat llams ekam ot oirt eht dewolla dna
.deksa ehS "?rewohs a ekat I dna uoy fi thgirla ti sI"
.rac sih ni flesmih detautis ramO sa
.noitceffa htiw mih rewohs dna
.em htiw setats eht ni evil dluoc taht elpoep rehto ees ot em degaruocne eh tcaf ni ,lla ta toN"
.tsiaw reh dnuora dedlof lewot a htiw tuo deppets iaM
.trihs etihw sih htaenrednu edils yltneg smra rednels reh
.tsev sih enodnu dna
.em ot gnivom yrev saw ti ,tub wonk I"
".reh fo em dednimer syawla yeht dna esuoh eht revo lla meht worg ot desu ehS
.sdnab tsiaw eht evoba morf tuo dekaep riah cibup etihw fo sdnarts wef a
.ramO ot txen tas eh elihw htiw flesmih naelc ot
.tiaw syawla nac erutuf eht
.eivom eht ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut eh erofeb
.kool luftsul a ot ,lufhsab ot
ekam dluow ecaf s'yrahcaZ snoisserpxe ynam eht yb detavitpac osla saw eH
.enilef eht edisni degdol llits htgnel sih htiw
.loohcs hgih ni kcab mih dehcaorppa dah iaM yhw yltcaxe wonk t'ndid eh
".gniht laer eht dah reven tub
.deretne ylwols dna dekconk yrahcaZ
,rehto hcae dnatsrednu yltcefrep ot demees yehT
.tnemom yrev taht ni ereht
,daeh sih dnuora delioc smra rednels s'iaM
.pu gniworg nedrag reh htiw rehtom pleh ot desu I tub
.delkcuhc ramO "?yttik ytterp
,dniheb morf mih guh yltneg iaM tlef yrahcaZ
.thgin eno naht erom rof stseug gnitsoh morf stneduts deyamsid taht ytlucaf eht htiw tcilfnoc esuac thgim taht sa
.taht retfa uoy wonk ot teg ot detnaw I …oS
.rewohs ot moorhtab eht ot dedaeh epoletna eht erofeb
.ylbatrofmoc elpoep eerht tif llits dluoc eh
"!hsinif uoy llit …gniog peek nac …uoY"
.raewrednu dna arb etihw ycal etacirtni na htiw
,tnemom eht ta yltnerruc toN"  .deksa yrahcaZ
,ni flesmih gnittuhs fo stibah dab dlo eimyts ro sracs dlo laeh ylluf reven dluoc
derettam taht lla
nam rehtona htiw etamitni reven saw ramO
",meop taht edam I nehw tem yllaiciffo t'ndah eW
.thgilnus eht ni tpek erew stnalp eht sa yad eht gnirud tuo deria moor eht dah ev’dluow eh ,yllamroN
”,seigrella ruoy pu raelc ll’yeht ,eseht fo emos ekaT
.spil sih morf deffup psag ykahs a
.htgnel s'yrahcaZ debbur dna dleh yltfos sdnah reh elihw eht lla
.retsaf depmuh eh elihw smra sih yb yrahcaZ nwod dleh dna
.mih dniheb rood eht esolc kcaM dehctaw eerht eht dna
.pot porc a dna strohs myg fo riap a naht ssel gnihtyna ni
"?raed ym flesruoy yojnE"
yad eht rof dniwnu ot nugeb dah enoyrevE
"?em rof gnimottob dnim uoy dluoW
erutuf rof ,goDdliWD2@ ,rettiwt no mih wollof nac uoY.sevitcepsrep
,noitalever neddus eht htiw seldnac ekil til erew srae s'yrahcaZ  .demaeb iaM
.segassem lareves htiw tahc puorg eht ni oirt eht degassem dah kcaM taht was dna
",neht gnitiaw syob owt uoy peek ton dna yrt ll'I ,lleW
,redluohs s'kcaM bur ot revo dehcaer yltfos ramO  .pu dekool kcaM
",stnalpesuoh taerg rof sekam taht nemiceps nacirfA tsae na
htolchsaw yrd llams a yrahcaZ dednah dna revo deklaw ehS
shgis dedniw-gnol dna
,yawllah eht fo dne eht dehcaer yeht ecnO
,trihs sserd sih ffo dils ramO nehW
,nepo rood eht draeh meht fo htob ehT
raelc edam saw dnim s'yrahcaZ taht htiW
,rehtegot sraey rieht lla nI
notuf eht morf pu tis yltfos kcaM was eH
,etatsorp s'enilef eht degassam yllacidohtem sregnif sih fo spit eht nehw ,tcaf nI
.desimorp eh ekil tsuj perp ot emit emos enilef eht gnivig
etatsorp s'yrahcaZ tsniaga pu edir t'ndid pit sih erus ekam ot flesmih dellortnoc eH
.ecnesba reh gnirud ylecin gnola nettog evah ot demees yehT
.mih htiw pihsnoitaler a detnaw llits I sksir eht htiw neve …tuB
.etaudarg syug ruoy erofeb netfo erom kcaM dna uoy tisiv lliw I dna iaM taht erus ekam ll'I
.ytisrevinu eht etagivan mih depleh I dna
.htgnel sih fo pit eht dnuora deifisnetni erusaelp fo hsur toh eht
esira dluoc taht melborp laitnetop ylno ehT
teef devooh sih otno dnats ramO pleh iaM dehctaw eH
,erutraped sih erofeB
esimorpmoc riaf a ekil demees tI
eht ta delevram yrahcaZ sa llat doots liat enilef gnol siH
.tfel I erofeb wodniw a nepo ot togrof I ,seigolopA“
.ytisrevinu s’yrahcaZ dehcaer oirt eht emit eht yb tes ot tuoba saw nus ehT
.od ot tahw wenk dna lortnoc etelpmoc ni eb ot demees ramO
.owt eht ot kcab denrut eh erofeb
.reh edisni dehsinif eh sa sesnes sih dellud
.mih edisni htrof dna kcab pmup dna eborp pit sih tlef yrahcaZ
.dias eH "!votoloZ kcaM m’I
.iaM ot guh eht nruter ot dnuora denrut eh sa dias yrahcaZ
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tekcop sih tsniaga etarbiv enohp sih tlef yrahcaZ
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ydob gnorts dna citelhta yrev a dial
,ylpeed dehsulb dna deddon yrahcaZ
.sey ,semitemos eb nac tI"
.semitemos ,haeY“  .delims ramO
,raeh ot yrros os m'I hO"
ot eb tsum ti tluciffid woh enigami t'nac I
elor a koot eerht llA
!tem reve ev'I eituc elbaroda tsom eht tsuj si eH“
,desirprus morf degnar hcihw
.elbatrofmocnu er'uoy fi ot evah t'nod uoY"
,ezis sih enilef egral a rof yzoc elttil a saw moor mrod sih elihW
.mih tsniaga debbur ylmrif
.rehtnap kcalb eht eldduc ot demuser dna yrahcaZ ot revo ti dednah eH
.pu deidit moor mrod eht htiw flesmih fo eifles a dna
”?teem uoy fo owt eht did woH
,dnim s'yrahcaZ ni dnA
",rehtegot teg ruo ot revo dneirfyob ruoy etivni ot evol eW
,dehsinif ramO ecnO
eldduc elpoep owt evah ot ecneirepxe wen ylevitaler a llits saw ti
.yrahcaZ ,wols ti ekat nac ew ,lleW“
wef a koot eh sa deddon ramO  .dias yrahcaZ
keehc s'yrahcaZ ssik ot ni denael ehS
.taht derebmemer uoy desirprus m'I .did I ,haeY"
ruf kcen sih ot pu delzzun ecaf s’ramO leef dluoc eH
hsur daeh toh evissam A
,noitatiseh tuohtiW .sreh otni dezag
.sreh tem seye sih
.delkcuhc dna egassem eht was iaM
.mottob ot nalp t'ndid I ,si gniht ehT"
.hgis yvaeh a tuo tel dna
.thginot rof enilced ot evah ll'I ,yldaS"
.taorht s'yrahcaZ ni pmul a demrof dah sdrow
.yrahcaZ rof tfig yadhtrib a esahcrup ot nrut s’iaM si ti won dnA
trofmocsid on dewohs yrahcaZ
.mih htiw evah uoy pihsnoitaler etamitni eht syojne dna ynapmoc ruoy setaicerppa ylpeed kcaM erus m’I ,llitS"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.elttob eht rof deb sih rednu nwod dehcaer yrahcaZ
.nohtaram a nar eh hguoht sa decap traeh sih
"?esaelp ,rewols tib a oG
elttil a pu gninepo flesmih dnuof eh
”?ereh kcaM evah uoy nehw netfo neppah siht seoD
.tib a delffins dna mra sih htiw ti dekcolb eH
.yrahcaZ ot yradnoces saw rehtegot noisses a evah did taht ton ro rehtehW
.nosrep rehtona htiw ti ecneirepxe dluoc eh taht ytinutroppo tsrif eht saw siht
…kcaM htiw deirt ev'I ,em eveileB
?raey namhserf ,rehtomdnarg ruoy rof etorw uoy tsetnoc meop a ni steloiV nacirfA esu uoy t'ndiD
mih otno dils iaM tlef yrahcaZ
.emit a ta nosrep eno tif ylno nac ti ,yldaS"
"?etammoor sih osla uoy erA
staoc ruf roloc tnereffid fo xim a emaceb notuf ehT
stnurg yvaeh tuo tel eh
.uoy ot tnaem ehs tahw dna ti otni luos ruoy deruop uoy hcum woh was I
…tsuj m’I .iaM ,enif s’tI“
guh mrif rehtona rehtnap kcalb egral eht evig ot revo deppoh kcaM
,kcaM htiw edam s'eh spihsnoitaler peed eht ot kcab kniht saw
,yrahcaZ ot resolc detoocs dah ramO
htgnel dekaos muc tew s'ramO ta erats tub pleh t'ndluoc seye s'yrahcaZ
.tsrif ni deklaw yrahcaZ ees ot denrut dna
.hteet etihw prahs sih revo delruc spil sih dna
,tnellecxe saw eH"
yrahcaZ otni flesmih demmals eh ,emit sihT
;lufhsab emoceb dah eH
.sserd reh odnu ot kcab pets reh dehctaw dna
,denetfos ecaf s'iaM
.edisni flesmih dils ylluf dna
.krowtra denoissimmoc dna
,iaM morf tuo flesmih edils ramO dehctaw yrahcaZ
.desuora llits saw rehtnap kcalb eht taht deciton osla dah seye sih
,htgnel sih ruotnoc sllaw enilef eht tlef eH
",ecneirepxe retteb a dah evah t'ndluoc
,mih dehcaorppa dna delggig iaM
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.raer retuo s’enilef eht tsniaga pals ot sllab sih desuac hcihw
,ramO ot kcab dekool eh erofeb
yrahcaZ edisni dehsinif dah eH
seye gnirussaer mlac sih
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.taoc ruf kcalb sih revo lla nedal saw taht muc ssecxe eht ffo naelc ot tius dewollof yrahcaZ
,sdnoces wef a nihtiW
.retaw fo elttob a mih evag yrahcaZ elihw
.yrahcaZ rof erusaelp eht fo hcum dedivorp sllaw lana retuo eht
.sdnah sih ni retaw fo elttob a htiw owt eht dehctaw dna pu tas yrahcaZ
;ewa ni derats yrahcaZ
,dessik yeht elihW
,gnimottob ot desoppo reven saw eh elihW
knurt sih ni meht erots dluoc yeht detseggus ramO
,snaom reh fo sdnuos eht
.mih ssik ot pu denael dna
ylthgil swalc s'raugaj ehT
kcab daeh sih werht ramO
,sfeirb kcalb sih ot nwod saw eh ecnO
.flesruoy dnuor erom eno og dluoc uoy ekil mees uoy
,ahtnanoi ailuaptniaS"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,pu dekool yrahcaZ
.eltneg eb esaelp tsuj
.mih ot revo dekool dna hgis yvaeh a tuo tel epoletna ehT
.tnemhsilbatse ihsus eht sdrawot klaw eht edam yeht erofeb
.detcepxe reven eh gnihtemos saw iaM ni tseretni na dekraps ti taht raeh ot tuB
.niaga revo lla ytinigriv sih gnisol fo snoitom eht hguorht gniog saw eh hguoht saw ti
.iaM ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut eh erofeb
.ralucitrap ni tnalp eno yb ni nward yletaidemmi saw yrahcaZ
"?stnalp fo seiceps siht ot nward er'uoy nosaer cificeps yna ereht sI
.hcaorppa ot seno eht eb meht tel ot tseb saw ti derugif eh ,llitS
".yrahcaZ uoy knahT"
,wonk uoY" ,deddon iaM
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.niaga kcuts erew taorht sih ni sdrow eht
,ssik mrif a meht fo htob evag ehs retfA
.llam eht ta tfig s’yrahcaZ rof gnippohs dehsinif tsuj ramO
,ekops eh erofeb tnemilpmoc s'iaM dna bur redluohs s'ramO morf derrup kcaM  "!erom uoy wonk ot gnitteg dnim t'ndluow I
nades yruxul cirtcele dehsival s'ramO fo knurt eht edisni ffo stfig s'yrahcaZ deppord yehT
.deyaws liat raugaj
erutammi erew taht steloiv nacirfA wef a derehtag eh dna
".terces a taht peek
.ramO rof devres dna deraperp eb dluoc taht sehsid nairategev fo yarra enif a dah osla secalp ihsus sa
”?tib a nwod pirts I dna iaM fi thgirla ti sI !hO“
rehtnap kcalb rellat eht revo demool ramO
dna neht thgir mih detroppus taht elpoep eht saw
.nades eht fo kcab eht ni tas dna degilbo yrahcaZ
.dehsinif dna naom dezinorhcnys a tuo tel yeht
,nwod wols ot nehw
.dekan moor s'yrahcaZ ni delttes yeht sa
traehteews loohcs hgih dlo sih was reven yrahcaZ
?mM"  .delbmum yrahcaZ "…seY"
.etatsorp ym tih uoy nehw evitisnes tib a …tsuJ"
.reh dleh dna resolc deppets yltneg eh sa
.ssik eht ekorb reven ehs elihw eht lla
.der emoceb ecaf eritne s'yrahcaZ ees dluow eh neht
.pu deeps ot nehw dna
.mih fo erac doog ekat ot nac ew lla od ll'ew ,esruoc fO"
!syug uoy teem ot ecin ,oslA
.stseug esuoh ot reisae ti edam hcihw yawllah eht fo dne eht ta saw moor sih
.mrod moordeb-eno a em droffa ylno nac emoh kcab stnerap ym ,on yldaS"
,ydob reh fo tnecs eht
.htgnel sih fo ruotnoc yreve xelf ylthgit sllaw lana s'enilef eht woh yllaicepse
.doohnam s'yrahcaZ morf flesreh deerf ehs
trihs sserd sih denesool ydaerla dah ramO sa dehctaw dna revo dekool yrahcaZ
,mih edisni dorp ylwols sregnif s'epoletna eht tlef yrahcaZ