.ereht erew enohpllec dna ,sdubrae sseleriw knip
",eit a htiw kool uoy woh ees s'tel ,neht woN
,mih erofeb ramO dna iaM was dna
",srefaol emos uoy teg ot deen tsuj ew woN
,ksa ot em rof thgirla s'ti fi
.evots sag elbatrop llams eht revo dehcnuh rehtnap kcalb rellat eht sa dehctaw eH
.tuo xob eht fo stnetnoc eht dils eh erofeb
.kciuq laer moorhsaw eht esu ot evah I tub ,seigolopA"
"?ramO ,nam emosdnah siht s'ohW"
.emussa naht rehtar kcehc ot refas saw ti ,llitS
;s'yrahcaZ tsniaga sserp ot spil llams sih dewolla dna
,tsehc s'rehtnap kcalb eht no sdnah sih detser kcaM
,yadot yadhtrib ruoy s'ti gniredisnoc ,lleW"
.mih no gnihgiew saw tol a dna
.etad txen rieht no rennid ot mih taert osla dna
,stnalp fo elbat eeffoc llams eht deraelc
.kcaM erofeb peelsa llaf ot tsrif eht saw rehtnap kcalb eht
.msagro na ot dneirf enilef llams sih gnignirb saw
,kcehc tnalp yliad sih demrofrep rehtnap kcalb rednels ehT
,deunitnoc yrahcaZ
dna retsemes tsal yrtsimehC dessap ydaerla ev’I"
,enod smaxe sih fo lla htiW
.yrahcaZ htiw drohc a kcurts dah ronaemed dexaler dna ,seye thgirb
,sivaD suiraD yb ”syaD egelloC“
.edarg gniliaf a gnitteg morf flesym evas ot ssalc a fo tuo pord ot dah …I"
enilef trohs eht tlef yrahcaZ
,esolc dneirfyob sih delzzun kcaM
",yrdlokcuc htiw gnorw gnihtyna s'ereht taht toN
s'kcaM ,rennid drow eht derettu eh nehW
"?thgirla s'taht fi uoy fo stnemerusaem emos ekat I yam ,neht woN
,selzzum s'rehto hcae ni decnad dna delgnimretni seugnot riehT
?wollef ramO siht tuoba tahw dna …ees I"
,won sraey owt rof snoitasrevnoc dah evah eerht eht elihW
,stneirtun erom dedda dna lios eht degnahc eh retfA
.owt uoy gnitteg m'I"
.woh wenk eh trofmoc tseb eht edivorp dna
,ylsseltroffe enod fi sA
,deddon rehtnap kcalb ehT  .deggeb kcaM
.ecin os gnihtemos gnitteg ot desu ton tsuj
raer yrruf eulb suoegrog s'enilef ehT
,skoob txet eht dekcats eH
.raew yadyreve lamrof erom rof rehtona dna
.kcab rehtruf tes erew
,riap a no dils yrahcaZ sa nooS
,stius owt eht esahcrup ot dedeecorp ramO
,gnineve eht rof tes saw emit eht taht was dna mrala sih ot deppilf dna delzzup saw eH
,gninrom eht ni ydaer gnitteg dneps ot dedeen eh emit ssel ehT
,spil s'rehtnap kcalb eht gnola dedilg eugnot
.guh a rof drawrof degnul yletaidemmi dna ot pu dekool kcaM
,worromot llit t'nsi ti wonk I"
.sih htiw deniwtretni sregnif reh yaw eht
trac eht edisni gniretne elihw
.skcart eht otno ffo deirrac gnieb erofeb esolc a ot edils srood niart eht dehctaw dna tas eh
,sllah erutcel eht edistuo mih htiw tuo gnah ot seitinutroppo ynam t'nerew erehT
.daeherof s'kcaM elzzun ot nwod denael dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.tsehc sih tsniaga demmals taht taebtraeh esnetni eht saw draeh eh lla
s'kcaM .tohsdoolb ylthgils seye sih dna
"!oot sweivretni boj rof retal ti esu nac uoy ,dnA
.debrutsid ton saw rebmuls yvaeh s'yrahcaZ
.erots gnihtolc s'nameltneg eht ot meht del eh
.kcab reh no tap llams a evag eh dna
.elffur ot rufkcen s'yrahcaZ desuac hcihw
reffo eht yb demlehwrevo emoceb ton ot tseb sih deirt yrahcaZ
enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,deremmilg seye neerg s'iaM
?I t'ndluow yhW" ,delims yrahcaZ
daeh sih dekcud eh
.pu flesmih smoorg dna
".kcab daeh ew ecno owt uoy teem ot evol d'eh ,haey tuB
.msagro sih ot esolc yrahcaZ thguorb taht hguone saw
,gnizama kool yehT
"?yaw eht yb gniod owt uoy era woH
repeels yvaeh a saw yrahcaZ taht wenk eH
pu daeh sih detlit kcaM sa dehctaw yrahcaZ
!uoy no elbaroda kool sdubrae esohT
sgnir lana s'enilef rellams ehT
saw pit nikserof yhcterts s'rehtnap kcalb ehT
.daeherof s'enilef llams eht ssik ot ni denael dna revo deklaw yrahcaZ
.taht ekil tuo gnissap rof yrroS"
,htaerb sih hctac ot deirt eh sa
,elims eht denruter yrahcaZ
.lanemonehp saw ytilauq dnuos dnuorrus rieht
.enilef trohs eht dnuora desolcne yltfos ydaerla dah smra sih
stcejorp gnitirw erutuf rof
,ciffart toof hcum t'nsaw ereht ,yllufknahT
,ylthgirb remmihs
.smra s'yrahcaZ ni peelsa llef enilef llams eht ,gnol erofeB
.tuo flesmih derit kcaM erofeb noisses elgnis a koot ylno yllausu ti wenk eH
,owt eht ediseb deklaw eh nehw dewolg noisserpxe s'ramO woh was yrahcaZ
dneirf raugaj elamef sih rof gnikool saw yrahcaZ
".raew ot em rof elbatrofmocnu dna thgit yrev em ot dnet yehT
,esnesnoN" ,delkcuhc ramO
.ecalp ni pmuj dna thgiarts dnats ot ruf sih desuac hcihw
"!em htiw ti evah llits I epoH
.gnihtemos uoy evig ot tnaem I
.esnopser sih egduj ot yrahcaZ ot pu dekool ehs
,pu denehserf ecnO
.moor mrod llams sih pu ydit ot dedeecorp eh erofeb
.evisnepxe repus gnihtyna em teg ot evah t'nod uoY"
.desuora ylluf emoceb yrahcaZ depleh hcihw
moor mrod eht edisni ria dloc eht detalusni ydob enilef egral ehT
,cinap fo hsur neddus a nI .gninrom eht ton
did snaej sih ,desuora rehtnap kcalb eht edam dah ramO morf sehcuot tfos ehT
.ot dah I ,no emoc yeH"
,yrahcaZ naht reilrae sraey owt gnitaudarg sevlesmeht dnuof ramO dna iaM taht won dnA
.spil s'yrahcaZ no kcep llams a decalp yltfos dna ni denael eh
.edis yb edis deyats yrahcaZ dna ramO sa dael eht koot iaM ,emit sihT
.delims yrahcaZ ",ni emoc esaelp
ylthgils dna delims rehtnap kcalb ehT
stneve eit kcalb rof llac snoisacco niatrec nehw rof enO
ygrene pu-tnep sih lla fo esaeler neddus eht dna ssalc a gnippord fo tneve gniniard yllanoitome eht taht derugif yrahcaZ
.regnol tib elttil a ylno
,no sehtolc sih dils eh
dluow ti ,elbatrofmoc er'uoy fi hguohT
tsal dluoc yad eht taht
...niaga ssalc eht liaf I fI
.esacriats eht sdrawot rood eht fo tuo nar dna ,seohs sih otni deppoh
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,elims mraw s'kcaM ees oT
.eseht em evig ot evah t'ndid uoY
.ezag eye sih tem dna revo dekool epoletna ehT
resolc detoocs yrahcaZ
.gnihsad kool uoy t'nod ,ym hO"
.tset ot gnos a pu dellup eH
.spil eht no reh dekcep dna ni denael ramO
".yadhtrib ym dnuora thgir tsuj nwot ni eb ot deneppah dna
,dniheb morf redluohs sih pat dnah a tlef neht eH
ni dehsur iaM tlef eh
,roloc eht rof seigolopA"
derreferp syawla enilef llams ehT
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa reeuq kcalb a
.iaM htiw pu hctac ot dna
.rehtnap kcalb eht ot eitkcen yerg depirts a pu thguorb eh erofeb ecnalg feirb a koot ylno epoletna ehT
.ekac eht nekat evah thgim siht ,yrahcaZ rof tuB
.deksa ramO "?tif eht s'woH
deraperp rehtnap
.seye sih debbur kcaM
,trihs s'kcaM htaenrednu s’wap sih htiW
.ylthgit s'iaM dleh sdnah sih
"!yrahcaZ ,yadhtrib yppaH
,gnisimorp demees taht stius owt tuo dekcip eH
.dnah sih debbarg iaM
"?dneirflrig dlo ruoy dna uoy neewteb enif llits gnihtyreve sI .ees I"
"?ecalp tsrif eht ni pu kaerb ot owt uoy desuac tahw
mih rof dleh ehs ytrap esirprus etarobale llams eht
.pu doots ylneddus eh sa llat doots srae enilef eulb eht
;ecap rewols eht dnim t'ndid yrahcaZ
.nosrep ni ramO gniteem emit tsrif s'yrahcaZ yllacinhcet llits saw ti
.derumrum yrahcaZ ",yrroS"
".lla si uoy fo lla rof tseb s'tahw detnaw …I
?dluow uoY"  .dereffo yrahcaZ ".pleh
ybsressap desimorp hcihw
.stfig eht rof tupni ruoy teg ot etairporppa erom saw ti derugif dna
.delkcuhc llams a htiw yawa dellup ramO sa sdnoces wef a rof ylno detsal
s'kcaM .dimuh emaceb meht dnuora ria eht
desaeler yrahcaZ
.yawa thgir ti sserdda ot tnatropmi taht lla mees t'ndid tI
.sehtolc sih dehcraes dna notuf eht dniheb tnew enilef rellams eht sa dehctaw yrahcaZ  .dias kcaM
.xob eht ta derats dna hciwdnas gge fo tib tsal eht dewollaws yrahcaZ
trihs sserd etihw eveels gnol dna
,smra s’yrahcaZ otni delwarc dah kcaM .rehtnap
.ytilanosrep citsaisuhtne revo myg elbbub lacipyt s'iaM ot ecnalab retnuoc a sa detca
",thginot yats em gnittel rof niaga sknaht dna looC"
.gnilrad ,kcab
,desaercni htaerb detnap dna derrup kcaM
.tekcaj eht edisni tekcop terces llams a ni yawa dekcut saw taht xob etihw llams a tuo dellup kcaM ,yllautnevE
cisum eht desuap eH
.tius wen a teg ot uoy ekat ot gniog si ramO
deb notuf eht morf tuo delwarc rehtnap kcalb eht
.noitces eohs eht ot denrut ramO
yrahcaZ rof tnatropmi saw tahW
.naem I tahw t'nsaw taht on hO" ,dehsulb kcaM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.segassem txet tsap morf serutcip eht revo dekool eh elihw
.stnalp eht lla retaw ot togrof eh tub taht ylno toN
.sotohp morp dlo esoht pu thguorb iaM sa dehctaw dna
revo seog iaM sa
moor llams eht ni deohce dnuos noitcus yvaeh a
yug a htiw pihsnoitaler repeed a evah ot detnaw syawla eH
thgirb erew skeehc s'yrahcaZ
.pets txen eht gnikat erofeb sgniht ssecorp ot emit emos rehto hcae evag dna
!yrahcaZ ,emac yllanif uoy taht yppaH"  .deksa yrahcaZ
egelloc dnetta ot ylimaf sih ni nosrep tsrif eht saw kcaM woh erawa saw yrahcaZ
.stnuoc taht thguoht eht s'tI
.daeherof sih dessik yrahcaZ
.htgnel s'enilef eht fo pit eht morf dezoo erp fo sdnarts gnol htiw resolc dehcni msagro sih
ecnedifnoc s'dneirfyob sih pu dliub ot thguos eH
.tey mih denekawa t'ndah mrala sih taht ddo tlef rehtnap kcalb ehT
,moor mrod llams eht ni rehtegot sruoh tneps owt eht sA
",gnol eb t'nod ,yakO"
?enilef eulB naissuR etuc eht ,hO"  .delims yrahcaZ
sehtolc sih otni gnilwarc ekil tlef eh ,yllanretnI
tisiv emoc ot em detnaw yehT
.kcaM guh ot revo denael dna
,stfig hsival tpecca ot yhtrownu tlef enilef egral ehT
.sserd kcen-V gnol elprup a ni
stsiruot dna ,stneduts egelloc ,seilimaF
.daeh reh detlit iaM
.yawa thgir stfig eseht tpecca ot thgir leef t'ndluow ti tuB
,wonk I" ,deddon yrahcaZ
,eman lluf s'rehtnap kcalb eht sa
,meht fo owt eht ediseb deklaw dna deddon yrahcaZ
enilno tuoba deklat syawla ev'uoy erots nedrag emoh eht ot uoy ekat lliw I dnA
.krowtra denoissimmoc dna
".od ot gniog m'I tahw wonk t'nod I dna ,erofeb ssalc a debmob reveN
.nam yako s'ti …yeH"  .pu sekohc kcaM
eitkcen eht gniyt dehsinif eH
".em rof gnihtyreve tuo kcip depleh ramO
.gnizama dnuos yeht ,kcaM meht evol I"
emocleW"  .redluohs s'yrahcaZ revo dekaep iaM
.seitisrevinu tnereffid dnetta ot gniog erew ew gninrael retfa rehtegot deyats ev'dluoc ew fi erusnu tsuj saw I
smra eulb yzzuf s'enilef ehT
ydob sih revo yduts ylluferac ramO leef dluoc rehtnap kcalb ehT
ramO dna iaM woh dnA
,ebyaM" ,delggig iaM
,edis ot edis morf dehctiwt liat s'iaM
.strihs sserd fo riap a htiw gnola eulb yvan krad eno dna kcalb eno
,yllaer toN"  .deksa yrahcaZ
.retal pu naelc syawla dluoc eh
,tuB !taerg s'tahT"
.sdoow eht fo kcen sih ni tisiv a mih yap ot emit eerf hguone dah yeht
,syawllah dna sriats fo htnirybal eht hguorht yaw sih delevart eh nehW
.seilleb rieht sllif
?rebmemer ,yrasrevinna ruo dna syadhtrib owt tsal ym rof stfig ynam os em nevig ydaerla ev'uoY
".rof kool ot tahw wonk I
.htaerb sih hctac ot deirt dna ylpeed detnap eh
.pal s'rehtnap kcalb eht fo pot no detaes
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,sezis dna seiceps fo tes esrevid a dedivorp sniuqennam lamina ehT
.seno dlo ruoy xif ot gniyrt yrarbil eht ni uoy was I hO"
s'kcaM .sessik etanoissap
.kcaM otni dees fo sepor tnes dna desaeler yrahcaZ
.ramO erofeb detneserp dna tuo emac eH
.spih egral s’enilef eht otno barg ot revo dehcaer dna
,noisses gnidir rewols a ot
?oot ramO htiw noitcennoc repeed a s'ereht ekil leef uoy od
.dniheb morf ramO dewollof ylkciuq dna devaw yrahcaZ
.saw tius latner etunim tsal taht gnittif mrof dna thgit woh derebmemer eH
eno siht piks esaelp
.mih detxet enoemos taht was eh
,goDdliWD2@ ,rettiwt no mih wollof nac uoY.sevitcepsrep
.od ylurt I ,snrecnoc ruoy dnatsrednu I" ,deddon ramO
,sdnah koohs yeht elihw hguohT
.pmur s’enilef eulB naissuR eht ot pu spih sih detsurht eH
.tuo flesym dehcysp dna elbat cidoirep eht rof sdrow hsilgnE eht lla eziromem t'ndluoc tsuj I
"?uoy ot doog dnuos hciwdnas eseehc dna gge na seoD
.srae s'eulB naissuR eht fo edisrednu eht dehctarcs dna dettep sdnah egral sih
",flesym deb ot daeh neht dna rennid emos ekam ot gniog saw I
".em tsurt ot uoy ksa tsuj I
s'kcaM  .sdnah sih ni dial taht senohprae knip sseleriw fo riap llams eht revo deiduts ylluferac
",depiw yllatot neeb evah tsum I
,stnalp eht retaw
.skcals eht dna ,trihs sserd eht
.nwotnwod tuoba dna tuo erew stneduts tsom dna yadrutaS saw ti
”syaD egelloC“   yojne esaelP
.emit gnol a rof dah ev'I seno retteb eht fo eno
"?eituc ,nwod uoy tog s'tahW"
,sniatruc niht eht hguorht dekeep nus eht htiw nevE
"…ro sruoy fo dneirf a tsuj eh sI
"?yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I …Z"
.elor evitca na ekat dna
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,setunim wef a nihtiW
.tuo dehcterts dna denway kcaM
flesmih ot delkcuhc yrahcaZ
.peelsa llits kcaM ees ot revo dekool dna
,spih s’yrahcaZ otni dednirg ylpeed kcaM
iaM htiw pihsnoitaler eht nepeed ot ytinutroppo ehT
revo ti deklat ew ,reh ot ti detseggus I nehW
.elbat eeffoc retnec eht no detarbiv enohp sih ,yliL hcaeP eht
,laem sih dehsinif kcaM sa tsuJ
.thgin eht dneps ot mrod sih ot revo emoc ot deksa kcaM .enilef eulB naissuR yknups eht
,pal sih denepo rehtnap kcalb egral ehT
,ecaf s'rehtnap kcalb eht ot esolc nettog dah ramO
.morp ecnis pu deffips siht uoy nees t'nevaH
1 traP ,sivaD suiraD yb
.aedi ym saw ti tcaf ni
iaM morf noitceffa llams eht deyojne yrahcaZ ,llitS
.sehtolc fo skcar eht sdrawot kcab denrut eh erofeb delkcuhc ylpmis ramO
,spetstoof dna snoitasrevnoc detarebrever llam eht fo sllah ehT
,skcart eht nwod pirt eht gniruD
,spihsnoitaler xes emas gniees ot desu t'nerew elpoep taht hcum os toN
,spil sih depacse tnurg delffum A
s'kcaM .tsehc sih ni detanoser taht srrup dna delbmum wol eht draeh rehtnap kcalb ehT
.mih ot pu delgguns dna ssik eht denruter yrahcaZ
,edisni yats ot segassem lareves enilef eulB naissuR eht evael saw won od dluoc eh llA
.seit wef a tuo dellup ramO
rebmuls peed eht fo tuo flesmih dellup eH
.llam eht ta ,ramO dneirfyob reh dna iaM ees ot gniog m'I ,yllautca haeY"
.doohnam s'yrahcaZ gnola dedilg spih s'enilef eht sa
deb notuf eht dedlofnu neht rehtnap kcalb ehT
.seno regnuoy eht rof elpmaxe na tes ot dah I ,thgir s'tahT"
…enoyna htiw eb dluoc ti fi dias eh dna
,deunitnoc ehs sa deddon yrahcaZ  ?thgir taht sI
"?worromot ,ramO dna iaM ees emoc ot elba er'uoy fi em ot dlrow eht naem
.uoy thguorb ev'dluoc I secalp rehto eht lla fo tuo ereh uoy detivni ev'I yhw gnirednow er'uoy erus m'I ,oS" ,ekops iaM
,tneserp llams eht tuo dleh kcaM
,noitatiseh tuohtiW
.tnaw uoy fi deb ym ni peels nac uoy ,thgirla s'tI"
!owt uoy ees yllanif ot dooG"
sllaw thgit s'kcaM yb kcab dellup
dnah sih no dloh reh desaeler iaM
.sraet deird morf nettalf ruf keehc yzzuf sih fo segde eht htiw
.rehto eht rof sgnileef eht gnidrager tuohtiw enoemos gniusrup tsuj ton dnA
.peelsa llaf ot kcaM dewolla hcihw
.retfa kool ot tnaem eh ohw esoht yllaicepse
.ssecca rof ksa ot meht no dekconk eh hguoht sa
"!ycnaf yrev gnihtemos em teg ot knab eht kaerb ot deen t'nod uoy niaga ,eruS"
pu doots srae s'yrahcaZ  .dias ramO
kcaM dneirfyob s’yrahcaZ htiw tcaretni
thgilnus tcelfer llam wodniw egral eht was neht yrahcaZ
.yrahcaZ ot flesti detneserp
.noonretfa worromot eerf llits saw eh fi ees ot ni gnikcehc iaM neeb evah tsum ti derugif eH
,mih revo demool llits eh elihW
,elbuort on s'ti hO"  .dias kcaM
;revo dekool yrahcaZ
nwo sih fo dnim a dah sdnah siH
.sih otno dleh ylthgit dnah s'iaM
".tuo pleh ot yppah naht erom tsuj
.elbuort on s'tI"
,kcaM dneirfyob sih saw ti taht was dna enohp eht debbarg eH
,sriats fo sthgilf wef tsal eht dehcaer eh ecnO
,dewollaws yrahcaZ
.notuf retnec eht no tas dna seohs sih ffo koot kcaM elihw egdirf inim eht drawot nwod dehcuorc yrahcaZ
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,drow a dias yrahcaZ erofeB
.flesmih perp ot kcab dehcaer eh erofeb
,esoprup htiw klaw ot demees epoletna ehT
.srehto rof trofmoc gnidivorp saw
bac etavirp a liah ot neeb evah dluow eciohc lacitcarp rehto ylno eht
.skcals ydnugrub htiw
.ekas s’emit dlo rof pu gnihctac erew yeht hguoht sa
egdirf inim eht ni kcab eno tup eH
.mra thgir s'ramO otno sgnilc dna
,ylsuovren dehctiwt liat
.thguoht ni tsol demees ohw
!taht ekil gnihtyna ro hsitef dlokcuc a ekil ton s'tI"  .ffo derepmat kcaM
.skcus hguorht gniog er'uoy tahw wonk I ,ton er'uoy tuB"
.erac sih ot gnikil a nekat evah stnalp eht
.tfig eht detpecca dna sraef sih edisa tup eh ,llitS
.mih dessik yltfos kcaM
.no meht yrt yrahcaZ pleh ot nwod deleenk dna
,etats derit sih nI
.yadhtrib sih etarbelec ot llam ybraen eht ot revo emoc eh detsisni yehT
.meht gniteem ot desoppo eb t'ndluow I ,esruoc fO"
,sdnoces wef a nihtiW
.llam eht ot yaw eht fo tser eht deklaw dna pots sih ta devirra eh
.emit eht ssap ot VT no seivom emos maerts ot pu deyats enilef eulB naissuR ehT
,don a mih evag dna
"?ylkciuq os gnihtemos dnif ot elba uoy erew woH
srefaol fo sriap wef a htiw denruter ramO
,enot dehsuh a ni dias yrahcaZ
emarf rood kcab eht fo pot eht gnittih dediova ylworran dna
.mih dnuora nethgit pirg senilef llams eht tlef eh
,reh sdrawot daeh sih denrut yrahcaZ
,evisnepxe ti edam taht ecnatsid eht hcum os t'nsaw tI
.moor mrod llams eht deidit dna
.daeh s'yrahcaZ otno dleh ylthgit
.snoitnetni fo tseb eht htiw siht otni gniog era uoy taht erus ekam ot tnaw tsuj I
.msagro pu-tnep sih desaeler enilef llams eht ,hcamots dna tsehc sih ssorca triuqs muc fo sdnarts gnol eht tlef yrahcaZ
;yrahcaZ ediseb tas dna revo deirrucs eH
kcalb llat eht ediseb peelsa nellaf dah kcaM
.emihc yreehc a evag dna yltnatsni decnys sdubrae ehT
daeh sih dekcud eh
.sedulcnoc etad s’yrahcaZ fo tser eht woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni
.stius etarobale fo naf gib a ton osla m'I
;notuf eht no kcab denael yrahcaZ
.thginot yats ot ecalp a dedeen tsuj
neknus ylthgils erew skeehc
"!detrats teg s'teL !taerG"
,txet s'iaM morf gnigduJ
.delkcuhc yrahcaZ
",emoh kcab sklof ym llet ot tahw wonk t'nod I
!gnippohs tuo uoy ekat dna uoy taert ew erugif I dna ramO
!oot noos etaudarg ot gniog er'uoY
.kcoc s'yrahcaZ morf flesmih deerf enilef rellams eht sa
.dnik oot raf er'uoy iaM"
.noitats eht sdrawot deggoj eh sa
duol a tuo tel enilef retrohs eht raeh dluoc eH
htgnel lluf s'yrahcaZ no nwod dedilg ylwols kcaM
.ssik a rof ni mih thguorb eh
.rehto eht nwod delzzug dna
,pu dekrep srae s’yrahcaZ  .resolc denael kcaM
;saw tnaem I tahW
drawrof denael kcaM
.tsehc s'rehtnap kcalb llat eht otni derehtoms saw ecaf s'enilef llams ehT
".traehteews ,sknahT
serots dehsilbatse hgih dna rengised erom eht elihw
.mra eno htiw yrahcaZ ot guh flah llams a evag
.cirbaf eht fo diov eht otni gniraeppasid dna
yltsoc nwotnwod gnilevart edam taht syawdaor egral fo kcal eht tub
.emit no evirra dluow eh taht reh derussa dna
.setunim evif ni traped ot tuoba saw niart gninrom tsal ehT
.ffo sdubrae knip sih htiw neve etartnecnoc ot enilef eht rof drah ti edam hcihw
.redro ni saw riap wen a erugif ...I
.rehtnap kcalb rellat eht ot pu gnikool ezag sih
.htap klaw eht gnola sdworc diova ot reisae ti edam tI
,pihsnoitaler nepo na htiw yako m'I hguoht nevE"
,htaerb sih rednu desruc rehtnap kcalb ehT
.hcneb ybraen a no tas eh erofeb
.deb sih no yal ot revo mih deirrac dna
,retsemes txen niaga ssalc eht ekater llits nac uoY .tiaw nac ti
.tfel dah eh nehw deb notuf sih ni peelsa llits saw kcaM
s'kcaM   .snaom sih elffum ot elzzum sih derevoc smra yrruf eulb sih
.mih ot pu dekool dna ekawa rits kcaM was eh ,moorhtab llams eht fo tuo deppets yrahcaZ nehW
,nwod dedlof srae s'yrahcaZ
;dnik ni dednopser yrahcaZ
.flesmih yojne dna ni evig ot enilef rellams eht delangis eh
,em htiw pihsnoitaler nepo na ni tseretni desserpxe ramO dna iaM nehw dnA
.llew sa uoy rof emos ekam ll'I"
.rufdaeh s'eulB naissuR eht dettap dna
.deneponu elbat eeffoc eht no tfel erew sados eht was eh nehw flesmih ot delkcuhc yrahcaZ
swalc prahs sih htiw nepo pat eht tuc ylluferac eH
.dehcaorppa dna pu doots epoletna ehT
.aera nwotnwod ysub eht revo denihs dna
thgil fo ecruos eht sdrawot decaf srewolf gnimoolb dna sevael ehT
,edam si ssem revetahW
.ramO dneirfyob reh teem ot mih rof deticxe yllaicepse saw ehS
tiurf fo tnemtrossa eht elihw nietorp rof gnivarc rieht yfsitas
!yadot retal kcaM teem ot deticxe m'I ,lufrednoW"
ecaf sih dedoolf doolb toh fo hsur A
,tnemeticxe s'iaM tuohguorht dehsulb
.moor mrod eht pu ydit ot dna
,tsehc s'rehtnap kcalb rellat eht no daeh sih dial kcaM
"?raey roines loohcs hgih did uoy ekil eno tner ot hsur ot evah t'ndluow uoy yaw tahT
.revo mih detivni dna ylper a tnes yrahcaZ
.seiduts sih htiw tuo mih gnipleh llits ,taerg gniod er'eW"  .deksa iaM
revo dedlof srae
.noitnetta etamitni dna lacisyhp erom rof ydeen saw kcaM nehw dnim t'ndid yrahcaZ
.stluser eht yb deifsitas
.noitceffa drawtuo wohs ot suovren oot tib a llits saw epoletna tnedifnoc eht neve ,teY
.ti gniodrevo saw bulc amard eht fo tser eht htiw
nerdlihc regnuoy eht ecitne ot serots htiw denroda saw ecnartne tnorf ehT
.htgnel enilef regnol eht gnikrow
,deksa eh tahw gniod rof egnahcxe nI
.ynapmoc s’ramO dna iaM deyojne dna
.evirra eerht uoy nehw elbatneserp
.swollip dna teknalb tseug eht tuo thguorb dna
"!ti ekil uoy epoh I
,sdnoces wef a nihtiW
.wolg nedlog sti ni kcaM gnihtab tesnus eht fo weiv eht derutpac eh
,yrahcaZ ot delffum erew sdrow ehT
.taht fo erawa repyh erew ylticilpmi lla yehT
.reh ediseb dekool eh emosdnah woh no tnemilpmoc s'ramO yb depleh ton saw hcihw
ecneserp drawtuo tnedifnoc tey mlac s'ramO
s'kcaM   .htuom sih edisni edils ot eugnot s'kcaM dewolla eh
.llam eht ta emit teem derised eht litnu setunim ytriht saw tI
ramO wonk ot teg ot tsuj etad llams a eb ot gniog ylpmis saw ti derugif eH
.nekat hcni elgnis yreve yojne dna rovas ot thguos eh
.dedaeh eh erehw rof evisnepxe repus saw hcihw
.epat gnirusaem ybraen eht debbarg ramO sa deddon yrahcaZ
,tekcaj eht morf gnihtyrevE
,ezis llams eht etipseD
esnopser kciuq a evag eh sa neercs eht deppat yltrepxe sregnif siH
…m'I taht os pu sdaeh a em evig ot erus eb tsuJ
.htooteulB sih pu dekooh rehtnap kcalb eht sa srae enilef sih ni meht ecalp yltneg kcaM tel eh ,deddon yrahcaZ
,kcaM tnes saw egassem tsal eht retfA
.stnemerusaem rieht gniwonk tuohtiw tius wen a enoemos yub ot esnes edam evah t'ndluow tI
.eritta tseb sih t'nsaw no tup eh tahw dnA
dna resolc denael ramO
.enil tsiaw s'enilef kcalb eht tsniaga degdun dna dekop dah lasuora suoivbo
hcnul ihsus tuo-ekat etirovaf sih fo emos mih evig dluow yrahcaZ
".mih eveileb ot tnaw I dnA
"?gnol uoy tpek t'nevah I depoH
.dah yeht lla s'taht dna ylkciuq gnilles erew yeht
spil s'yrahcaZ no kraps yratnemom eht hguohT
,edis ot edis deyaws liat
.doohnam s'rehtnap kcalb eht morf ffo flesmih edils ot pu detfil ylwols spih sih
.setunim owt ni traped ot tuoba saw niart eht taht smocretni eht revo draeh eh
…llitS" ,dehsulb yrahcaZ
,tnalp tsal eht ot dednet eh erofeb hguohT
shtnom rof ti tuoba deklat flesym dna ,ramO ,iaM
.tisiv s'worromot rof flesmih moorg dna naelc ot moorhtab eht ot dedaeh eh ,dehsinif ecnO
eseehc dna gge ehT
yawa dekool yrahcaZ
,net rednu ni enod eb dluoc noitats eht ot klaw eht elihW
.gnitser morf debrutsid eb t'ndluow dna
,tellaw sih ylno taht dnuof dna
htiw dnopser dluoc eh lla saw don daeh elpmis A
,lasoporp eht tpecca yltsedom ot deirt dna
.dehsinif tuoba tsuj ew mu ,haey hO"
.tnaw uoy gnihtyna kcip uoy tel dna
eye rebma s'rehtnap kcalb ehT
.ecnartne eht ot revo deyesom dna
".emas eht did I emit tuobA
.seton dlo ym lla tpek I
,noihsaf iaM lacipyt ni hguohT
.mih delosnoc dna ediskcab s'kcaM debbur dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.boj taerg a did ylniatrec eH"
"?retfa er'uoy iaM tsuj ti si rO
,redluohs sih dehcnup yllufyalp kcaM  .dias yrahcaZ
.hgis dedniw-gnol a tuo tel dna delffins eh
repap gnipparw gnikool evisnepxe htiw delaecnoc ylluferac saw xob ehT
",ytaews lla eb dna etal emoc ot si tnaw I gniht tsal dna ,worromot nur ot deen I sdnarre wef a evah I
stekcop sih hguorht gud eH
.llam eht ta detagergnoc dna dexim lla
s'kcaM  "?riap wen a dedeen I wonk uoy did woH
.ezis dna seiceps ruoy etadommocca lliw taht dnim ni erots tcefrep eht evah I
!togrof I ,toohs hO"
.detraped ehs erofeb keehc s'ramO no ssik a evael ot revo deppiks yllufeelg raugaj ehT  .deilper ramO
.daeh deralf eht delaever dna
,yrahcaZ fo pot no detser dna drawrof denael kcaM
,eruliaf a ekil leef tsuj I"
elzzum sih morf tuo gnuh eugnot s'rehtnap kcalb ehT
,elzzum sih denepo
”.pleh em tel ,ereH
!ruoh na revo rof gnivird neeb evah I dna ramO
.moor gnignahc eht rof dedaeh dna sehtolc eht debbarg dna
.secaf rieht no nroda selims mraw
".gnihsinelper deen taht seilppus emos era ereht erus m'I
.esle enoemos rof stius tuo dekcip ev'I emit tsrif eht t'nsi siht tuB
.trac niart eht otno deppets eh erofeb sriats fo sthgilf wef eht pu mih deirrac sgel tsaf sih
",lliw I yrrow t'noD"  .dehsulb kcaM
.egaugnal dnoces a sa hsilgnE gninrael rof ydaerla trams ytnelp er'uoy ,netsiL
smra gnol sih ni kcaM eht pu depoocs rehtnap kcalb llat ehT
.ylwols ekops yrahcaZ "…ramO yeH"
meht fo owt eht rof sehciwdnas gge dna eseehc wef a deraperp ylkciuq yrahcaZ
,doohnam sih fo ruotnoc yreve dnuora dehcnelc ylthgit sgnir renni s'kcaM fo noitalumits dedda eht htiW
,ssik eht detpecca dna nwod daeh sih denael yrahcaZ
?won tius a tuo kcip dna dnif ot esnes ekam ti t'ndluoW
.yrdnual sih fo tser eht dedlof dna
,thguoht dnoces a tuohtiW
.trups htworg rehtona tcepxe t'ndid I esuaceb saw tahT" ,dehsulb yrahcaZ
"?ebab ,worromot rof snalp yna ,oS
,sehtolc lamron sih otni kcab desserd saw yrahcaZ ecnO
gninaom dna gnilims kcaM fo thgis eht tsuJ
,detarbiv enohp siH
s'kcaM .lworg suonevar duol a htiw laem a rof denraey hcamots
,ot deen t'nod uoY"
.noisserpxe worbeye desiar a mih evag rehtnap kcalb llat eht
.tsehc eulb yzzuf llams s'enilef eht delzzun dna pu detfil daeh sih
.ni peels ot dewolla saw emit erom eht
delkcuhc ramO  .dehsulb yrahcaZ "…iaM"  .delggig iaM
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
",emit ni tsuj devirrA
.ni eulB naissuR trohs eht democlew dna revo deirrucs yrahcaZ
rae sih ta yawa elttar seton ssab tfos eht tlef yrahcaZ
dniheb dekool yrahcaZ
rehtnap kcalb eht rof srefaol fo riap a dna ,strihs sserd
.mih erofeb enilef eht no saw sucof niam s'ramO ,daetsnI
.stekcop sih fo ynnarc dna koon yreve hguorht gud sdnah s'enilef ehT
peed htiw mih gnirewohs
.osrot dna noitcesdim sih erusaem ot esolc emac ramO nehw
,won thgir ti tuoba meht llet ot evah t’nod uoy kniht tsuj I
"!meht evol dna etaicerppa I tuB
,evitcartta enilef llams eht dnuof syawla rehtnap kcalb eht elihW
.yaw sih no saw eh mrifnoc ot semit lareves mih degassem dah iaM
sllaw s'kcaM fo sdlof renni mraw eht tlef yrahcaZ
.ediskcab s'rehtnap kcalb llat eht otni gud yllufyalp swalc reh
.stius tsap ot derapmoc ytilibom retteb dah eh dna
.ylleb s'yrahcaZ tsniaga depmuht muc erp fo stelpord ynit
.seiresrun tnalp roodni ynam eht fo eno ot dedaeh oirt eht sa sgab eht yrrac pleh eh detsisni yrahcaZ .peek ot
"!kcaM ,dneirfyob ym morf tfig yadhtrib a erew yehT"
.nirg gnivorppa na evag ylpmis ohw ,ramO ot revo dekool rehtnap kcalb ehT
seye neerg s'kcaM .rrup elbidua
deralf htgnel
.kcid sih fo eniltuo eht edih ot elttil
.eros ssel pal sih edam ti
.ti yb ffo tup t'nsaw ramO taht sepoh ni
,yllautca dab oot toN"
.em ekil enoemos htiw eb dluow ti
.mih ta derats dna nwod denael eh
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.ti ekahs ot tuo dehcaer dna
rehto hcae rof edam demees owt ehT
.enohp eht rof dehcaer dna
ramO ot revo dekool eH
.pleh ot ereht eb nac I dna
.txen rof perp uoy pleh nac I dna rehtegot meht revo kool nac eW
,trihs-t eveels gnol etihw tuo nrow A
.lwob parw citsalp a htaenrednu hserf tpek llits separg dna
,stnalp eht ot dednet dna flesmih ot demmuh eH .yhtlaeh dna
.won elihw a rof sdubrae wen dedeen I
tsev neerg a nrow dah
.taert ym si ti ,xaleR"
pu dekool yrahcaZ
",ramO ,uoy wohs nac I su fo sotohp wef a evah llits I kniht I
,ramO dneirfyob epoletna ehT
.kool eht setelpmoc eit eht ,erehT"
moortser eht sdrawot dehsad ylkciuq yrahcaZ
.sbmil ynniks s’enilef eht derusaem eh elihw mih sserac yltfos sdnah sih dna
,pal s'rehtnap kcalb eht tsniaga flesmih dednirg eh sa seye sih desolc kcaM
.seton hgih naelc erup eht htiw gnola
.taes nepo ybraen a no tas dna
deddon yrahcaZ  .dias ramO
",esaelP .em edisni esaeler …Z"
,detaslup kcid nikserof llams ehT
.noops regral eht sa gnitca rehtnap kcalb eht htiw
,hguoht yllautnevE
.dniheb morf rehtnap kcalb eht degguh iaM
"?htiw elggurts uoy did tcejbus tahW"
.lworg hcamots s’enilef eht ta ecnayonna sserpxe t'ndid yrahcaZ depoh eh ,nwod dekool dna
.ydob rednels sih dnuora parw ot trats smra s'enilef trohs eht tlef eh
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
seirots trohs gnillepmoc etaerc ot yaw a sa gnitirw sesu ohw
!thgir s'tahT" ,deddon iaM
".kool ot truh t'ndluow ti sseug I …lleW"
tuo dellips muc yna esac ni pmur s'kcaM htaenrednu lewot a decalp yrahcaZ
,meht dniheb tuhs rood eht htiW
",ecnahc a meht evig ot detnaw I
.keew slanif gnirud yllaicepse
".ramO ,siht otni uoy depor ehs fi yrros m'I
xaler ylluf ot elba flesmih dnuof yrahcaZ
".oga emit gnol a snrecnoc ruo tuo dekrow ev'ew ,esruoc fO"
,tnorf ni ramO htiW
,revo dezalg seye s'rehtnap kcalb ehT
.pu ekorb ew taht tluaf reh t'nsaw ti …lleW"
.esab eht dehcaer dna
.rehtnap kcalb llat eht morf secnalg leets netfo dluow epoletna eht
.evisnepxe gnihtemos t'nsaw tfig eht taht deyarp eH
"!yrt a ti evig no oG
.keehc s'kcaM fo renroc eht no demrof taht raet llams a yawa pihw ot
.srekaens detadipalid emos dna ,snaej emos
",pihsralohcs ym esol ll'I
.ti ekam ot erew eh fi nur ot dah eh wenk yrahcaZ
wap sih desiar yrahcaZ
revo dehcaer yltfos eH  .dias yrahcaZ
.syek moor mrod sih togrof eh
.ekahsdnah mrif a ramO reffo ot tuo dnah sih dehcaer yrahcaZ
"?oot rof yduts ot sessalc rehto evah uoy t'noD
.mih revo derewot dna pal s'rehtnap kcalb eht otno delwarc enilef trohs ehT
ramO htiw eno wen a ot flesmih nepo dna
"?ti ekil llits uoy epoh I
.sevitcepsrep wen ot sredaer nepo dna
.loohcs hgih ecnis taht ekil dnah reh dleh eh ecnis sraey neeb dah tI
,yrtsimehC"  .deksa yrahcaZ
.seirossecca dna stius dedaerht enif fo noitceles tsav eht yb demlehwrevo
,doohnam s'rehtnap kcalb eht ekorts dna ezeeuqs ot nugeb dah kcaM
dnuof eh tnemyojne niam eht
.tseretni tseb ym retfa gnikool er'uoy dalg m'I dna
,erofeb thguoht ylsuoiverp eH
.reffo suoreneg a hcus htiw mih desirprus dna daeha tnew ehs
.sgnignoleb sih dessessa dna flesmih revo dekool yrahcaZ
,meht detacirbul dna sregnif sih dekcil enilef rellams ehT
"?yako gniod uoy era ,yddub yeH"
!eno wen a redisnoc tsael ta ot truh t'ndluow ylbaborp ti llits tub
.ylbatrofmoc tif dah skcals dna tius yvan krad eht ,esirprus sih oT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.rood eht ta kconk a draeh eh
.deretsulf yrahcaZ
.tnof tnagele dlob egral a ni detnirp saw ,remmiZ yrahcaZ
"?tsedle eht er'uoy ,oS ?yllaer hO"
kcalb ehT  .kcaM htiw gnidniwnu fo tcepsorp eht ot drawrof dekool yrahcaZ
dennirg epoletna dennat ylthgil ehT
"?sdubrae etuc esoht teg uoy did erehW
.seceip elzzup gnissim ekil roolf eht no derettacs sehtolc htiw dekan nwod deppirts erew htob ,gnol erofeB
,esruoc fO" ,ni demihc ramO
.esolc hcni ot elzzum sih desuac hcihw kcab sih denethgiarts dna
!yrahcaZ ,uoy teem yllanif ot desaelP"
.kcoc sih ot gnilc
dehsiw ylterces eh ,dnim sih ni dnA
.notuf tuo daerps eht no tas eh erofeb deb eht ffo detoocs dna
.meht rof tif thgir eht dnif nac nam yna taht
.wef a yb ssap ot deneppah oirt eht
.enilef eulB naissuR eht ediseb tas eh dna sados emos debbarg rehtnap kcalb ehT
cisum emos htiw ciffart og dna pots eht tuo nword ot sdubrae knip eht ni deppop eH
,nwod dekool kcaM
.ramO htiw erom gnihtemos si ereht kniht ot ekil …I"
.ylthgit rehtnap llat eht otno dleh ylthgit dna
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,delkcuhc yrahcaZ
.eit s'yrahcaZ gniyt tpek ti sa
",htaerb peed a ekat tsuJ
,gnimusnoc emit erom dna
,htgnel etairporppa eht ta erew seveels ehT
.stnap rieht odnu ot nageb dna nwod dehcaer tac eulB naissuR ehT
.enilef llams eht deniard yletelpmoc evah tsum
,edis ot edis morf spih sih degdun kcaM
.sih htiw dekcol seye eulb yerg s'epoletna eht
sredluohs dna daeh sih derewol yrahcaZ
,etarbiv ylthgil ot eugnot sih desuac gnirrup
tiurf fo lwob egral a htiw gnola
,erolpxe ot tfel llits noonretfa eht fo hcum htiW
,sivaD suiraD yb ”syaD egelloC“
,ydob sih elgnarts ylthgit t'ndid ti
.rehtnap kcalb rednels revo dehcnuh eht ot txen rellat ylevitaler mees mih edam dah erutsop thgirpu s'ramO
.mih sdrawot sdnah reh denoitom iaM
.oobat tahwemos llits era sgniriap yromaylop ,rehtaR
",stif ti woh ees dna no eno eulb siht yrT
llehs sih fo tuo mih gnirb ot hguone saw tI
.nedrag lacinatob llams sih otni demrofsnart saw moor mrod llams sih ,won dnA
.moor mrod eht otni deruop thgilnus gnineve eht sa sevael nref neerg hsul eht revo deiduts seye s'yrahcaZ  2 fo
.srehtorb regnuoy ym rof semit fo ytnelp ti enoD"  .deilper yrahcaZ
.yadhtrib sih rof stfig htiw dehsival dna deliops eb ot tcepxe t'ndid yrahcaZ
,ruf daeh s'kcaM dettap ylthgil yrahcaZ
.yrahcaZ ekil senilef egral htiw tlaed taht noitces a hcaer ot
,edis ot edis morf deyaws liat
llam eht sdrawot dedaeh rehtnap kcalb ehT
.sdnekeew no yllaicepse
.loohcs hgih ecnis yllacitamard taht degnahc t'nsah yllaer ehS
deggas erew sdil eye s'kcaM woh was eH
.mih ot pu dekool dna
.tsehc daorb s'enilef eht deppat ylthgil dna
.spil s'enilef eht depacse naom gnidnuos eninimef a
sevlehs dna selsi fo htnirybal eht hguorht daert sevooh teef sih
,ti dessim dah eh fI
.delbmum kcaM "…yrahcaZ"
"!ramO ,dneirfyob ym si ereh ,yawynA
.dilos a mih od ot kcaM no yler ot dedeen eh emit tsrif eht t'nsaw tI
,tsinatob a sa ybboh ruoy htiw ,sulP
.ti rof krow ot evah t’ndluohs uoy …kcaM“
",Z ,eciton a hcus no gniksa rof yrroS
.esolc yrahcaZ thguorb dah hcihw ,msagro eht tuohguorht yllacidoirep dexelf
,sdnah sih detegdif dna nwod dekool yrahcaZ
",tisiv a su gniyap rof uoy knahT
.dias iaM "!kcab eb ll'I
.rovaf eht rof mih yaper dna pu mih rettub ot woh yltcaxe wenk yrahcaZ ,revewoH
.raor tnurg wol a
,eraps ot etunim a ylerab htiW
,railimaf dna mraw tlef dnah tfos s'iaM
!yadhtrib yppah tub
rehtnap kcalb ehT
.saw eciov sih evaus dna htooms woh tsuj deton dna
".rehtegot tuo siht krow nac eW
"!neht ecnis thgieh emas eht deyats ev'I
,edisni dedaeh yrahcaZ erofeB
deretaw yletauqeda saw eno hcae erus gnikam
,tsehc sih ni niap fo egnit llams eht etipsed detsisrep yrahcaZ
.won elihw a rof hcuot ni tpek llits ev'ew ,tuB
"?ekil uoy fi won revo daeh nac eW
daeh sih deddon kcaM  .deksa yrahcaZ
.teem ot ydaer er'ew ekil leef I dnA
.tekcaj tius sih htaenrednu edils sdnah s'ramO tlef dna
.moor mrod eht ta kcab
.syar mraw s'nus eht ni sevlesmeht teknalb dna
.dnuora dneirfyob enilef rellams eht gnivah dnim t'ndid eH