.kcalb denrut yks ogidni ehT
.ereh dewollof dah esahC taht sepip eht otni detarapes neht dna
.tnemevap eht no dekcalc sregnif suonitarek sih dna ,devaeh tsehc sih
.rotagilla eht htiw regnol on saw ynnub eht tuB
,htolc yerg a htiw naelc ti depiw dna gum ytrid a otni taps tar ehT
.segnih sti ffo gnignah
:htuom stI saw erutaef rehto ylno sti ,seye eht htaeneB
.seye sih denepo dna
,ylkaew delggurts eH
,mih ekatrevo noivilbo tel tsuj dluoc eH
.evom t’ndluow tsuj ti tub
.thgim sih lla htiw dnah sih detsiwt esahC neht dna
,moor eht fo edis raf eht nO
,deunitnoc ti ",revewoH"
.knird sih ot denrut neht dna
.erutaerc eht htiw laedro reilrae sih morf derevocer ton llits
.tnemom a rof noisiv sih gnirevoc srats cipocsodielak eht
,kcoc degrogne-llits sih ot nwod og seye s’tar eht was esahC
.ykrej dna wols sbmil sih
.thgiew s’llub eht rednu dekaerc ti dna ,loots eht otno llaf flesmih tel esahC     regguR .P .B yb
,gnitae rof tnaem yllanigiro selbat eht fo eno no
.deruoloc-ssom dna drah
,ni knus snroh sih sa hcleuqs neerg-tons a saw erehT
,wohemos ,tnereffid tlef tI ?hself
,eulb kaew ,elap a
.flesmih revo lla knird neerg eht fo emos gnillips ,teef sih ot tpael esahC   .mrif tey mlac
.ereh eid dluow ynnub siht dna eh won dna ,eid ylimaf sih ,eid sdneirf sih tel dah eH
.esahC ot emac nalp A
,tas knuks a ,mih ediseB
loots eht ffo mih gnitfil saw ti ekil tlef sdrohc rewop eht fo enord waszzub eht won tuB
,hcaorppa mih dehctaw tar knip ehT
,ertnec eht morf tuo gnidaerps skcarc
.sregnif sih htiw ti ecart dluoc eh tuB
emit siht tub ,erofeb esirprus yb erutaerc eht thguac dah eH
,mih dleh taht saw ti revetahW
.laruttug dna peed ,deoom eh dna
,srats cipocsodielak ni dedolpxe noisiv s’esahC
.saw gniht siht revetahw hctac ot ediw deyalps smra ,tsrif snroh
,ydob sih ffo trihs s'esahC dellup ehs
.evom dluoc eh lla erew sregnif sih tuB
,yerg denrut der ehT
,yawa denrut ti nehT
.nwonk ydaerla dah eh sa
.ydob sih hguorht eralf cinap wolley-nomel a tlef esahC   .wohemos ,gnorw
,levon tsrif sih no krow ta drah si eH
;draeh neeb evah ot dah skcik siH .ni nar esahC
.tsal eht naht redrah dna rekciuq emac pets hcae sa etihw tnecsednacni yllanif dna ,wolley neht
,hgual sih ni dnA .dehgual esahC
.yella eht hguorht yaw sih edam esahC
,denrut ezah krad ehT
;ibasaw ekil mih tih tub
,ti ffo gnippils tpek seye siH
,regnorts gniht siht ekam ot demees dah ti
.enog saw gniht ehT
,hgual gnilbmur ,peed a saw tI  .dehgual esahC
.esahC saw os tub
.htooms sdrow neergder sti ,dias gniht eht
.tsalb neerg dna eulb krad rehtona htiw tuo mih ekat ot gniraperp ti leef dluoc eH
.mih dellef evah dluow
,gnirats mih thguac knuks ehT
.yllufniap ,snroh s’esahC ffo flesti gnillup saw ti ,saw ti revetahW
si yrots s’yadot dna
,denekaew saw erutaerc ehT
.nar esahC ,nwod daeH
.mih tsniaga ydob elohw reh desserp ehs neht dna ,kcoc s'esahC revo daerps wolley ehT
,ti htiw gnola dewollof esahC
,mih naht retrohs toof doog a hguoht
.llot rieht ekat t'ndid swolb eht naem t'ndid taht tuB
,ynnub eht fo srae elprup gniwolg eht was esahC
,loots sih no denrut esahC
ecaf s’tar eht nehw
.hguorht nees …tlef eH
,ereht ydaerla wolley eht pota yal tI
,mih tih ruoloc fo bolg rehtonA
,erutaerc eht sdrawot pets a ekat ot nageb esahC
.enam aihcsuf a htiw noil a evres ot yawa deklaw tar eht nehT
moor egral a otni denepo tI
;llub a saw esahC dnA
.llaf ot demees tsuj yehT
.eenk eno ot flesmih dehsup esahC
,regguR .P .B ecalperiF eht fo dneirF yb ”deifirreT eM ruoloC“
.gnilbbarcs derolocitlum elap a dna
.deneppah ,mih ot deneppah revetahW
,dedeeccus rehtie dah eH
.noitcif ot kcab gnimoc speek dna ,7 ta gnitirw nageb regguR    .dlo taht si eh ,seY .5991 ecnis fo trap neeb sah eh hcihw
.pmil og ydob sih tlef esahC dna
.ynomrah fo eulb ehT
.mih revo gnidnats gniht eht ,yal ynnub eht
,hself htiw tcennoc fooh sih tlef eH   .saw ti reverehw
.tuo ekam t’ndluoc eh ,saw ti tahw tub
,dna ,ssik eht ekorb ehs
.stsaerb reh sa wolley sa tuo emac swap reh dna
.yella dne-daed ,krad a dehcaer eh nehw
raelc dna llits saw thgin ehT
,dedisbus der eht sa tub ,niaga cipocsodielak enog dah noisiv sih thguoht esahC ,tnemom a roF
,skcilc tnim etaciled eht was esahC nehT
.won thgir htaed ot ti taeb dna erutaerc eht ot pu og dluohs eH
.regnorts emoceb gnihtaerb sih gnittel
,ruoloc fo edit eht tsniaga sserp ot deirt dna ,snolat sti ot tog erutaerc ehT
.ssap regna eht tel dna dehtaerb esahC
,ylkciuq emac skcilc redneval thgil ehT .degrahc dna
.gnihtaerb saw ti ekil tsomla
.yawa dellup erutaerc eht dna
.desserpmi saw eh
.evila os dekool dah ynnub tahT
.tnemevom yna rof gnitiaw
.thgirb os erew sruoloc eht ,tniuqs ot dah eh ,niaga meht denepo eh nehW
.rehtegot dewolg yeht dna
.ees dluoc esahC ruoloc fo pord yreve morf
.siht od dluoc esahC
.elbat eht no nwod tas dna deppils esahC dna
,sirraH .I.D ,eman lagel sih rednu noitcif elggum setirw eh hguohT
,elap dna tniaf saw ti hguoht tuB  .detsiwt dna kaew
,elbat eht dnuora devom esahC dna
.mih evoba ssih calil a draeh eH
”deifirreT eM ruoloC“
.emit siht ti ffo edils t’ndid seye sih tub ,gof etihw-kcalb fo psiw a saw erehT
,eldnah rood on saw ereht tub ,rood eht dnuora tlef esahC   .rood A
,atnegam lufyalp dna thgil a sdlrow sih ,ekops ynnub eht
,eslup ti ees dluoc eH
,roolf eht no yal yeht sa ,dnA
,knird dnoces sih ot kcab denrut esahC
.pu flesmih dellup dna
,kcoc sih ta nwod dekool eH  .ohce
.eraperp dluoc gniht eht erofeb egrahc ot saw won epoh ylno sih
,sgnidliub eht no pu hgih swodniw eht
,roolf eht gnola kcilc redneval thgil a edam teef stI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.hcaer sti fo tuo flesmih gnipeek
.degrahc gniht eht nehT
.taht fo tsalb dnoces a evivrus dluoc eh erus t’nsaw esahC
.nwo sih fo lliw on dah eh hguoht sa
.elprup fo tsug a ni tuo gniog ria eht
.sselefil dna llud kool pat eht edam ti morf emac taht diuqil neerg suonimul eht dna
.…erom dnoces a tiaw ot deen ylno dluow eh—
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,keirhs noillimrev a saw erehT
.tniap s’god eht morf wolley dewolg llits hcihw ,kcoc sih ta
,dehcaorppa gniht ehT
,ecafrus cillatem yreve tub
.noisiv s’esahC dellif sruoloc gnilriws dna
,niaga mih tih ygrene neerg dna eulb krad eht
.dehsarht erutaerc eht sa
.wobniar lluf eht otni tilps
.eid ot gniog won saw dnA
”,uoy teem ot eciN“
.oot ,niaga llik ot epacse
.roolf dna selbat eht revo kcab gnirettalps dna sllaw eht gnikirts
.pu flesmih ecrof ot deirt eh dna
;cra ediw a ni gel sih gnuws eH
.won ,od ot erom gnihton saw ereht dna
.ereh fo tuo teg ot dedeen eH
.llaw eht tsniaga spitregnif drah sih fo elbmur llud eht ot gninetsil
,sdlof reh otni repeed gnidils
.og meht tel ot emit saw tI
.redduhs rood eht tlef eh tuB
.niaga mih hguorht tnew cinap deruoloc-nomel eht sa koohs sgel sih
od dluoc esahC llA
,ynnub eht ta ecnalg erutaerc eht was eh tuB
,dedisbus dnuos eht sA
.yltcaxe tahw erus t’nsaw eh
.tnaidar saw gnihtyrevE
;ssam cinagro ,yrebbulb a ot detcennoc saw esoh ehT
.oot ,denekaew neeb dah esahC roF
,emit siht rekaew saw tI
.thgil wolley htiw dewolg kcoc sih dna
:meht gnidiova on saw ereht tub
.ruf s'esahC tsniaga gnibbur stsaerb wolley gnislup ,mraw reh
.tuo mih yrrac ot evah dluow esahC
.mih dnuora dekool neht dna
.pans etihw a htiw flah ni gnikaerb dna elbbur eht fo pot no gnillaf llaw raer sti
gof a ni wodahs a ekil saw ti
.edisbus ot nageb ssih ehT
.eerf saw erutaerc eht
.tsehc desopxe s'esahC no gniwolg sgnikram reh
.eman tpa na saw reweS cirtcelE taht ssefnoc ot dah eh
,ti hguorht nar serbiF
.gnihtemos no thguac sregnif sih
.dedeen eh rab eht saw sihT
”,llub a flesmih esu dluoc ynnub taht ekil skooL“
.tnurg egnaro na fo
.ni flesmih nword ot lohocla hguone tuoba derac ylno eH   .erac t’ndid eh
.ssalg eht tsniaga gnikcilc slian prahs sih
.mih tih ygrene eulb dna neerg krad eht
”?htaed ni sdad ruoy denioj uoy litnu knird ot ereh emoc uoy t’ndiD“
,erutaerc eht ta dekool eh sA
delppot erutaerc ehT
.bolb eht otni repeed mih deirrac mutnemom sih tub ,pmil tnew ydob siH
,ynnub eht detades wohemos dah ti
”.niaga liaf t’now I“ ,dias dna
.gnippots fo ngis on dewohs dna
…was dna denrut esahC
.won enog erew yehT  .kramirB dna
.ytilausnes fo ezah a otni gnidnelb lla
.kcab sih ta ti leef dluoc esahC
,tsehc sih pu swap reh nar dna
,ereht gnihtemos saw ereht wenk esahC—
.rab eht ot kcab decnad dna ,tlik sih pu dekcip esahC
,dnuorg eht no derettil hsart eht ta
...tih snroh s’esahC
.mih deksa eciov yerg a
.otni denepo rood eht taht
,diuqil neerg ylbissopmi taht ta kool tsal a gnikat ,dna ,dias esahC
ykcul dna—thgir saw eh fi tuB
.cisum eht fo enil ssab eht htiw deslup dna ,seye sih erofeb delriws sruoloc ehT
,dessap tnemom taht tuB
dertah erom fo lluf maercs nosmirc a delruh ti sa evom t’ndid htuom tahT
.ynnub eht morf poog erom gnitcartxe llits saw ti was esahC tub
,nosmirc denrut der eht tub ,esir ot deirt eH
,ni devac dah rood ehT
,tnew yeht sa tuo daerps sa erew serbif eht litnu detiaw esahC
.niaga mih no krow t’ndluow dah ti rewop revetahw yllufepoH
.emit hcum dah ynnub taht kniht t’ndid eh
.roolf eht tih dna
,dellor yllanif esahC
;lworg hguor a tuo tel esahC
.yawyna gniklat ekil leef t’ndid eH
.esoh a otni poog gnilriws a gnitercxe saw rehto eht dna
.yella eht otni kcab deklaw esahC     .neht ,yella ehT
.ti hguorht ecreip snroh sih tlef eh ,saw ti revetahW
.wenk esahC ,gnol tsal t’ndluow gnidliub ehT
;kcoc s’ynnub a otno nwod flesmih gnirewol rotagilla na ees dluoc esahC
...ni emit tsrif eht rof evila gnileef ,dehgual esahC
.ti tuoba yrrow ot evah t'ndid eh os
,esahC tih ,egnaro erif ,ruoloc fo bolg rehtonA
,pat eht rednu gum eht tup tar ehT
.erom on ees dna raeh dluoc esahC ,yllaniF
,doolb ward ot ton hguone thgil
,dessih gniht ehT
.dworc eht otni yawa deppiks
deruobal sih dna ,roolf delit eht no eulb-yks dekcalc sevooh s'esahC
.won sselesnefed saw eH
.trihs s’esahC rednu meht dils
.niaga meht nepo ot ygrene eht evah d’eh fi erusnu
,neddih gnihtemos rof gnihcraes ,llaw eht gnola sregnif sih nar eH
,ynnub eht no …dnah …eno dah gniht ehT
,etunim a rof dnuorg eht no yal esahC
.efil sih evas ot emit ni yllufepoh—
elkcuhc auqa na htiw dednopser ynnub eht
;won revo saw ti taht mih dlot eciov yerg eht tuB
,gnispalloc mih dniheb gnidliub eht was dna
”…fo erom owt evah ll’I“
.esir ot delggurts esahC dna
.ssalg eht fo segde deggaj eht morf demrof saw lipup eht erehw
.erofeb mih ta gnigrahc neeb dah ti nehw naht detarutas erom hcum os ,teloiv erew skcilc s’erutaerc eht dna
.roolfecnad eht no sruoloc gniwolg eht saw ees dluoc eh llA
.dnah rehto sih htiw elbat eht ot no gnidloh
.htgnerts fo tuo gninnur yldipar saw esahC dnA
,nolat yhself a ekil gnihtemos
.pu gel eno detsioh eh
.emit siht ti ni ruomuh laer fo tib a
ylbaborp dluow erutaerc ehT
der deraor esahC
,emit emas eht ta thgirb dna krad saw tI
.thgil dna kcalb fo gof a ni yawa nups erutaerc eht tub
.esahC fo tnorf ni retnuoc eht no gum lluf eht degnab tar ehT
.elaK dna adgaD ,spup sih dna ,enahpetS ,nettik sih htiw adanaC ,awattO ni sevil regguR
.flesmih rednu sgel sih teg ot elbanu ,ynnub eht dna
.mumixam ot pu tsartnoc eht denrut dah enoemos ekil dekool ti ,niaga seye sih denepo eh nehW
.thgil sti ni ogidni dewolg yks eht dna ,tnaillirb
,ereht yal tsuj esahC ,daetsnI
.ecaep ni mih evael dna ,tuo og d’yehT
.tar knip tnaig a fo ecaf eht otni dekool dna
.ruoloc fo deniard tsuj
.nolat eht ees dluoc eH
.drah mih tih dah sknird esohT
.srae sti fo wolg elprup eht dezingocer eh ;taht fo erus saw eh ,reilrae nees dah eh ynnub eht saw tI
.yawa devom erutaerc eht sa pets hcae relap gniworg ruoloc eht
.mih drawot roolf eht ssorca decnad
,neht dna ,flesmih ydaets ot tnemom a koot eH
.thguoht yllaitini eh naht eman a tpa ssel demees ”roolfecnad“
,srallod xis tuo dellup dna tekcop sih ni deporg esahC
;eulb thgindim saw eH
,won stsalb esoht rof deraperp saw eh hguoht nevE .wenk esahC
,elgnatcer egral a saw tI
,yella eht nwod gnikool dna
.cisum eht ,wow ho ,dnA
pu detaolf ti sa
.sselefil dna yerg gninrut ,eno yb eno tuo og sruoloc eht dehctaw esahC
,niap eht tsniaga drah seye sih desolc esahC
wolg noen eht morf edisa—
.meht dehsup tahw ees t’ndluoc esahC
.tnatsid dna llams erew stelpord ehT
…leef dluoc eH
.mih fo pot no dednal esahC sa
.tuo evag htgnerts sih yllanif litnu yella eht dna rood eht hguorht thgiarts gninnur tpek tsuj esahC
. tnecsednacni erew lla
,mih ta ediw gnilims
.drah saw tI  .degnahc
,edis rehtie no yal sgnidliub llat owT
knahT .noinapmoc
,dne eht ni did enoyreve ekil tsuJ .esahC won dna
.dnopser t'ndluow tsuj ydob siH
:ruoloc tnarbiv was eh ,dekool eh erehwyrevE
,retsaf werg gnilbbarcs eht ,daetsnI
.rorret kcalb erup saw ti won
.retnuocne tsal rieht retfa pu teg ot elba neeb ylerab dah esahC woh
,esu dluoc eh snopaew on dnuof tub
,dna ,esahC ot pu dils ehS
,hctaw tsuj ot tnetnoc demees tar eht tuB
,thgir lla gnicnad saw erehT
.duht neerg-kcormahs a htiw roolf eht ot llef dna
,nat dna nworb ,saw eh ereh dnA
.saw ti tahw tuo ekam t’ndluoc esahC …htiw saw tI
,erofeb lasuora htiw raef dexim
,krad saw yella
yldliw snroh sih gniws ot saw evitanretla ylno eht wenk esahC dna
,cisum eht dna ruoloc eht ni hsawa saw eH
.worht neve dluoc eh gnihton
,revo mih ekat ygrene s’cisum eht gnittel
,mih fo tnorf ni doots eno dna
.sselniks tub ,yhself saw tI
,kramirB dna ,noJ dna ,narasleD ekil tsuJ
?ti t’ndah ,nuf neeb dah tahT
.taf ylleb fo reyal sih htaeneb selcsum lufrewop eht tlef dna
,detiaw dna cinap wolley eht demlac esahC
,erofeb ti derongi yltsom dah esahC
spil sih epacse htaerb fo lirdnet wobniar a was esahC
.gnidliub eht edisni gniees tsuj saw eh taht desilaer eh
.mih ediseb pu emac erutaerc eht ,mih fo tnorf ni gniraeppa fo daetsnI
,kcik rehtona rof kaew oot saw eH
.tsalb taht fo swodahs elap erew skcatta esehT
.yaw eht del llits yeht tub
lluf ehT   .rood eht tuo dna
.eromyna derettam meht fo enoN
;elbat eht ot no gnidloh llits saw eh dalg saw esahC
.noisiv sih hguorht esor niap wolleY
.pu erew secnefed sti lla
nwod dekool esahC
.elkcub ot nigeb ti ediseb llaw eht ees dluoc esahC
,ssalg nekorb ekil erew seye stI
,cisum eht ot gninnips dna gnihsom slamina fo stros lla
.rab eht fo sthgilkcalb eht htaeneb gniwolg lla
,mih yrrac thgiew sih tel dna
,ni kcab dellup serbif eht nehT
,rab eht ssorca nar eh nehT
.daer ti ”,5$ ,sknird llA“
;mih fo tuo tnew htaerb ehT
.tixe edis eht ot yaw sti gnikam saw dna
,redrah gnitteg daehkcoc sih leef dluoc esahC
:yella eht dnuora dekool esahC
.nur saw od ot dedeen eh llA
.llaw eht fo tser eht morf ti hsiugnitsid ot lla ta gnihtyna ees t’ndluoc tub
.retnuoc eht ssorca ti dils eht
.nwod tnew ti sa taeh esnetni na htiw sesunis sih dellif ti
,ylthgils os reve tsuj delims dna detnurg eh nehT
.sdlof reh tsniaga gnidils
.detniop dna ,dias esahC
.htaeneb eulb gnihtemos gnilaever ,tuo gnidaerps serbif eht
,tnemom a rof ynagoham detnap esahC
.nar esahC neht dna
”?yap lesmad eht seoD“
.sthgil tsethgirb eht gnoma flesti edih dluoc dna ,wohemos ,efil dna thgil fo mih deniard tI
,enog saw erutaerc ehT
.kaeps llits dluoc erutaerc taht dna
,der ot elprup morf ruoloc yreve gniwolg ,skcoc dna stsaerB
,redluohs sih revo mih werht dna
.erom dna erom delkcub sllaw ehT
,ria eht otni tpel ydaerla dah esahC
,reh edisni pils ot gniog saw kcoc sih thguoht eh nehw tsuj tub
,wolley yltneiciffus gniwolg swap reh
.deppots eb dluoc ti tuB
dah eH  .tuoba derac eh gniht ylno eht saw taht dna
tnemeticxe ni dereviuq srae elprup s’ynnub ehT
,gnilkcub llaw eht derebmemer eh neht tub
.sffup dlareme gnitnap
.ecaf sti fo tsom pu dewollaws evah ot demees dna
.hguone saw taht tub
?gninnur no gninnalp tsuj saw esahC dna
.ydnac neerg gniwolg eht htiw pu htob meht gnillif
,dah eh gnihtyreve htiw devohs eh dna
.derekcilf evol fo der ehT
,egnaro denrut sevooh s’esahC fo kcalc ehT
,ti tih dna ecaps ediw eht ssorca gniws dluoc sgel sih ebyam tub
,dessorc smra kciht sih
.tfel dah eh sevreser revetahw gnisu
.tnemom a rof noisiv sih demmid ylerab tI
.enog saw niap eht ,dnoces a nI
.os did ehs sa trihs s'esahC gnitfil
dne on dah taht diov kcalb egral a
,esahC dellif edirp fo hsur teloiv eht sa neve tuB
tnarbiv dna thgirb
.hsulb fo spsag wollahs tub duol ni emac htaerb siH
,mih elcric ot nageb erutaerc ehT
.ni delbmuts eh sa rab eht fo eman eht ta decnalg neve ylerab
.egar fo nooram ehT
.drah ,mih dessik neht
.ti wenk eh dna ,dehctamtuo saw esahC
,kcen s’ynnub eht otni desserp yeht sa nayc gniwolg hteet s’rotagilla eht
:yojne esaelP    .gnimag dna
ylleb s'esahC revo meht debbur ehS
.yella eht fo tuo debmilc ro nwolf
.ynoga tub gnihtyna rof maercs enimrac s'erutaerc eht gnikatsim on saw ereht dnA
,elprup saw eciov siH  .dias tar eht
.knird tsrif eht degguhc dna ,rab eht no nwod yenom eht demmals esahC
.srenwo rieht htiw nwod dna pu depmuj
,tuohs ot deirt dah esahC ”.oN“
,gniod neeb dah ti revetahw ,dnA
,nwod enohs noom
.tsehc gnivaeh sih lortnoc ot delggurts dna
.dedolpxe bolb eht neht dnA
.yhw yas t’ndluoc esahC hguoht ,ta dekool gnieb saw eh wenk esahC dna
.niaga ecno yella eht til
.bolb eht dehcaer dah esahC tuB
.eriseD fo ytitnauQ ehT
,snroh sih revo swap reh debbur ehs sa
.yoj fo wolley ehT  .ytuaeb fo neerg ehT
,ynnub eht dleh taht elbat eht dehcaer eh ,yllaniF     .ti erudne saw
,niap der eht tsniaga seye sih desolc eH
.spil sih morf depacse
,nwo sih ekil tsomla dekool tI
,yella eht ot nepo llits saw rood ehT
.kcalb tsomla saw—seidob
,erutaerc eht morf tpure maercs nosmirc gnicreip a was esahC .drah
,dluoc eh sa drah sa dezeeuqs eH
.noisiv sih derucsbo taht sruoloc tnecsediri eht tsap gnihtyna ees t’ndluoc llits eh dnA
.gnillaf morf flesmih peek ot elbat a debbarg eH
.eulb dna neerg dna wolley dna der strap yb
.ynoga der demaercs ydob s’esahC ni tnioj yrevE
.yhw yas t’ndluoc esahC dna
,niaga mih tih ygrene neerg dna eulb krad eht tlef eH
,tlik s’esahC didnu ehs nehT
,nwod daeh sih thguorb dna
.flesruoy no nedrub a tsuj saw egaR
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,og mih dehctaw esahC
.wolb ykcul a dnal ot epoh dna
,emit a ta hcni na dnah sih devom eh nehT
,rettihc wolleyeulb a draeh esahC   .eid dluow eh ro
.niaga ecno nrub eht tsniaga seye sih desolc eh dna
.enif saw taht tuB
,sdnoces nihtiw moor eht derevoc dah yeht
,neht dna ,top reh otni kcab dehcaer ehs ,deifsitaS
.ereht niks etaciled eht kram dna ruf eht trap ot hguone drah tub
;gnirob eb dluoc eh ,lleW
,ydob sih hguorht dna gel sih pu debbats deR
,moor eht ssorca tohs ruoloc fo sbolG
.drohc lacov larutannu na morf ruoloc elbissopmi nA
,tnemevap eht ni kcarc a no thguac sregnif s’esahC
,yssup reh fo der eht tsniaga desserp kcoc sih fo daeh talf eht leef dluoc esahC
.neerg dna eulb krad
.noitoved fo ogidni ehT
mih tih taht eno tsrif eht fo rewop eht htiw tsalb neerg-eulb krad a
.resolc emac erutaerc eht sa ogidni denrut teloiv ehT
.ecaf s’ynnub eht no rorret fo kool eht derebmemer eh tub
.gnihtemos eulb taht otni
,deretlaf pirg s’esahC
ynnub eht ffo erutaerc eht decrof dah eh tuB
,llub ylrub gib a yb devas eb ot detnaw syawla dah I“
,ti hguorht deidde sruoloc
”.woc elttil citehtaP“
,tnemom a rof kcab derettiks erutaerc ehT
,yks ogidni peed eht ta pu dekool esahC
,srae s’esahC tih drow noillimrev eht sA  ”!eiD“
ecaf sti was esahC
.saw ti tahw aedi on dah llits eh dnA
,tnemom a rof ylno
?ereh mih llik gniht eht dluoW
,saw ti revetahw otni sregnif sih gud eH
.txen eht otni denrut dna ,llah tsrif eht hguorht sepip eht dewollof eH
,snroh s'esahC debbarg ehS
.ynnub eht eb ot dah taht srepmihw egieb eht was esahC dna
doolb eht fo eulb eht dna
.mih ot gniod saw erutaerc eht revetahw ot nepo ynnub eht tfel siht taht esilaer dluow erutaerc eht ,retal ro renooS
htaerb esuertrahc fo psiw dipisni na dna ,ylkaew devom tsehc sih
.ylwolloh delkcuhc esahC
.der dna etihw dna kcalb
,noJ dna ,narasleD fo
.ynnub eht ta kool ot egru eht thguof esahC
,eerf emoc flesmih tlef esahC
,kcoc s’esahC gnikorts nageb ehs ,emit sihT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,ereht saw eh taht won tuB
ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ saw sihT.yks eht otni
.tnemevap eht no nosmirc dna drah gnikirts sevooh sih ,nar dna
.dekool esahC erehwyreve sruoloc fo ssam gnilriws a
.lla retfa sselesu saw eH
,tsiaw reh ot detleb top a otni dehcaer ehS
,erom ecno kcarc eht ni thguac spitregnif kcalb siH
.niaga draug ffo erutaerc eht hctac ot elba eb t'ndluow eH
.erutaerc eht morf tsalb rehtona yb tih saw eh sa neve
.erom hcum os saw ereht tub
,timda ot dah esahC
.esahC hguorht esruoc egaR
:etal oot tub ,ti ta snroh sih debbaj esahC
,delbmuts eh dna ,esahC tih der fo bolg A
.rethgirb sruoloc eht
.mih ni detseretninu yletelpmoc tub ,edis sih tsniaga gnisserp
.eulb looc a ot demlac htaerb sih ,elihw a retfA
.ti wollof ot elba eb d'eh kniht t'ndid esahC
.seot reh no pu gniog
”,ylkciuq os em dnif ot uoy tcepxe ton did I"
,detsixe reve eh tegrof ot lohocla hguone knard eh elihw mih dloh dluow loots eht tuB
,serbif ymils eht neewteb edils nitarek eht gnileef
,raor eulbwolley a ot deifisnetni maercs ehT
,xaler ot nageb esahC sa tsuJ
.airetefac a neeb ecno dah taht
.tsal eht ot thgif dluow eH
,ruf der yb dednuorrus yssup reh dna wolley thgirb gniwolg srae dna stsaerb reh ,god A
.decnad dna nups taht srats eht dna
.laroc eciov sih ,deksa esahC
,ti ees dluoc esahC
.erutaerc eht dna flesmih neewteb elbat eht tpek esahC
,mih gnilcric llits erutaerc eht
.dleif fo tros emos yb rehtegot dleh
.spat eht ediseb ,rab eht no nwod gum eht tup neht eH
.thgil eulb sti htiw yella eht pu til doolb eht yadot—yadot tuB
.krow dluow ti fi aedi on dah esahC ,ffo ti llup dluoc eh fi nevE
,meht dehcuot eh erehw wolley denrub sruoloc ehT
,elprup depsag eH
.hguorht klaw ot mih rof hguone gib tsuj
.eno rehtona htiw od dluoc eH
,ylkaew sgel sti gnivom saw ynnub ehT
,slamina ynam woh swonk ohw dellik dah erutaerc tahT
,cisum eht ,xes ehT
,kcen sih dnuora meht gnileef denigami eh won dna
…dednuos eciov eht dna ,erif eulb ekil
,rab eht no kcab gum ytpme-flah eht tup esahC
.thgil was ylno seye s’esahC sa neve ssenkrad ni flesti gnivael
,won ytpme dna llud erew sepip ehT
,tsif sih gnuws esahC dna
,dehsup dna ,dluoc eh sa ria hcum sa ni dekcus eh
,elbat eht revo mih dekconk tsomla dna
.nalp bmud a saw tI
”.em fo pot no despalloc eh nehw kcoc elbazis sih htaeneb dehsums eb ot tcepxe ton did I tub
,mih dessik dna ,niaga esahC ot ni denael ehS
.hcni hcae neewteb htaerb rebma gib a gnikat
.devaeh tsehc sih drah woh rettam on ,ni kcab ti ehtaerb t’ndluoc eh ekil tlef eh dna ,ypsiw dna yerg
,gnithgif peek ot dah eH
.yawa teg gniht siht tel ton dluow esahC
.erofeb nees reven dah esahC gnihtemos
,slirdnet sti neewteb depees ruoloc eht sa neergder maercs ot nageb tI
,teews saw tI  .degguhc eh
,snroh sih morf wolb ykcul a rab dnA
.noitanimreted fo elprup ehT
.thgil fo ezalb a htiw noom tnaillirb taht detcelfer
.tnurg wolley a draeh dna
.kcoc sih ni traeh sih fo taeb yreve tlef dah eH
.mih delleper ti fo trap emos hguoht sa
llah eht hguorht sdiuqil tnecsediri
,gnimaercs wolley draeh esahC
.lrans telracs a gniticile
.niaga dekcik dna ,niap eht rof flesmih deraperp esahC
;dnuorg eht tih daeh s’esahC ,yllaniF
,tnemevap eht fo fooh sih deppat esahC
.ti tespu dah esahC ,ylraelC
,mih dnuora sgnidliub eht ffo ohce ti draeh dna
.mih evoba ngis eht ot detniop dna
.yawa teg t’ndluoc dna delapmi llits saw ti ,saw ti revetahw
.nur ot edam saw eh
,tuo snroh dna nwod daeh
.dluoc eh sa drah sa rood eht dekcik dna ,pu deraer esahC
”?noissaP kniP toH gnilwoH s’solraC deirt uoy evaH“
,sepip eht fo ruoloc yreve detcelfer sllaw etihw stI
,bolb yrebbulb eht ot saw kcab sih litnu detiaw esahC
.…dna ,gniht noitatumsnart yrebbulb eht ot teg ot hguorht tnew poog eht taht esoh eht ta dekool eh ,daetsnI
.mih kcurts ti erofeb ti tih dluoc eh epoh ot dah tsuj eH
.mottob ot pot morf revo esahC dekool dna
yldam gnirekcilf ti nihtiw eulb eht
.tsehc sih ssorca dedlof smra gib sih
.erhco dessih gniht eht dna
.nosaer rehtona rof kcab emoc dah esahC dna
tniap s’god eht fo esuertrahc ehT
,rebma krad gnioom
.nirg gnireel a htiw nodnaba citsinodeh eht gnihctaw
,cra ediw a ni tsif sih gnuws eh os
”.esahC s’eman yM“  .tibah fo tuo dias esahC
...yks thgin kcalb eht
.rae s'esahC ot egnaro peed dednuos lworg ehT .delworg eh
”,yrreP dicA“  .eye sih thguac eno neerg thgirb a
.…yb kcab dehsup erew yeht
.ogidni peed a gniwolg epirts sti
.detsixe evah dluoc denigami reve esahC naht
.yldi deciton esahC
,stsif sih htiw erutaerc eht wollof t'ndluoc eh
dettimbus ylsuoiverp sah ohw
…gnilims saw ohw ,ynnub eht ta revo dekool esahC
.redluohs s’esahC revo detniop tar ehT   .yrgnA  .elbavommI
”.taht yrt ll’I“  .duola daer esahC
,moor eht fo elddim eht nI
,lirdnet a sa tuo emac ti tub
,degrahc esahC   .gnillats saw tI
.wenk esahC ,tseb ta erusaem yraropmet a saw sihT
,eulb thgindim eno siht
.kcams neerg tew a htiw
.flesmih fo erac ekat ot dah esahC woN   .dehtaerb eh tuB
.detarutasnu dna llud saw ti tub
”.ygrene eht uoy evig dluow taht erus m’I“
”,rab ym ni gnoleb t’nod tahT“
.egrahc sih pots ot elbat eht tsniaga flesmih decarb dna ,desruc esahC
,tsehc sih htaeneb sdnah sih ,yllaniF
,gniyd thgil sti ,noom ehT
pets tsal eno koot eH
.yawa teg ton dluow gniht tahT
.maelg ecafrus yreve gnikam thgil sti
tsehc s’gniht eht fo tuo trups diuqil eulb tnaillirb emos dna
,nus eht naht rethgirb enohs taht noom eht
.niarb sih ni tuo esle gnihtyreve nword taeb eht gnileef
,yella eht fo tuo dekcab ylwols esahC
.llaw raf eht tsniaga kcab tohs saw ti tub
”.nialpmoc t’nac ,hu ,I ,dias tahT“
.no dloh dluow eh dnA
,tfel sruoloc lanimil fo elpuoc a erew erehT   .tser dna
.thgil sti morf neerg enohs tar knip eht fo swap ehT
.dnif dluoc eh taht hctiws ro revel on dna
ylleb s’esahC otni dehsup stsaerb reH
”,efil sih evas I retfa ynnub evitaicerppa eht kcuf ot derit oot ton m’I ,seisatnaf ym nI“
nwod gnimoc sevooh sih ,delbmuts esahC
,mih fo tnorf ni llits tar eht was dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,rehtona ot yawllah taht morf sepip eht dewollof eH
;edirp fo llews llams a deruovas neht eH
.eciov egnaro na ni deksa ynnub eht
.yerg llud a ot demmid yella eht ni latem eht lla fo maelg eht dna ,dnuorg eht ot nwod kcab despalloc eH
.regna sti tlef esahC dna
,noitaicerppa ni delworg ehS
,ni pets dluoc yeht erofeb tub ,gnineppah saw dab gnihtemos taht was slamina wef A
.tniap s’god eht fo wolley llud eht was dna
.oot ,taht naht erom saw ti tuB
,dlot eb hturt ,dnA
.niaga esahC tih ygrene neerg dna eulb krad eht nehT
,erofeb mih tih taht ygrene emas eht tlef eh
.sllub degarne fo dreh a ekil dednuos ti litnu gnidnuober
.dnuora kool yllanif dluoc dna
.devom gnihton tuB
.htaerb calil fo ffup a ni mih fo tuo tnew tfel dah eh ygrene elttil tahw dna
.t'ndluoc tub ,mih fo ffo llor ot deirt esahC
,evom ylerab dluoc esahC
worbeye eno dehcra tar ehT
,saw ti revetahw fo ydob eht ta deggut daeh siH
,erofeb erew smra s’tar eht gib woh deciton t'ndah esahC
”,worros ot s’ereH“
.teef s’gniht eht fo kcilc tnim etaciled eht was esahC
,thgilnoom eht ni denetsilg dna enohs tI
,regnol gnikool deredisnoc ylfeirb eH
.noivilbo ot yenruoj sih no dessap eh rab tsrif eht saw ti esuaceb ni gnilbmuts tsuj
.meht neewteb skcarc eht otni sregnif kcalb sih gud neht dna
,ereh saw eh taht won hguohT
.ezorf esahC nehT
.rekaew ynnub eht dna
.enaw ot nageb noom thgirb ylbissopmi eht neve ,ylwols ,dnA
;ynnub eht ta nwod dekool esahC
,snac egabrag ot sliardnah morf
.noissap fo egnaro ehT
.thgirb enohs dna seye sih tih lla ti
,seenk sih no saw eH
.t’ndid esahC gnihtemos wenk eh hguoht sa
.tser ot emit saw ti
gninetsil rof uoy
.niaga eulb looc a ot demlac yllanif htaerb sih erofeb
,detnurg tar ehT
.retsaf saw esahC tuB   .tsaF
.taht nees dah esahC
,ynnub eht pu dekcip esahC
.eromyna did eh kniht t’ndid eh
,gum dnoces sih pu dekcip esahC
kcilc prahs eht draeh dna
hguor dna ymils gnihtemos …tih ti tlef dna
,tnurg egnaro na htiw
,devruc ti dnuora thgil eht hguoht sa
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,htgnerts sih derehtag esahC
.emit emas eht ta lla ,yrd dna tew dna tfos dna drah saw tI
tilnoom ehT    .yks eht ni gninnips ,thgirb denihs srats eht nevE
.kcab delbmuts esahC dna
stnemalif tnereffid dnasuoht a fo edam erew ti hguoht sa  dna
”?detnaw uoy tahw siht t’nsI“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sevooh dna stsif sih gnisu gniht siht thgif ot evah dluow eH
,ti dnuora tneb thgil eht ;tuo gniht eht ekam t'ndluoc llits esahC
.dnuora dekrej gnieb daeh sih tlef dna
.gnivom deunitnoc ezah eht nehT
…stserc ,srehtaefliat ,senam ,skwahom tuB
.neerg dna eulb krad
.ynnub eht edor eh sa hteet s’rotagilla eht fo nayc ehT
,moor eht dnuora dekool eH
.dekrims tar eht dna
,gnidaer ,gnitfilrewop
.dlareme erew shtaerb
.thgil fo ecnesba eht ni yerg krad sllaw knalb
,niap ni detsetorp gel siH
.roolfecnad eht otno dna
;spat tnecseroulf eht ta dekool esahC
.ot flesruoy gnitoved htrow gnihton saw erehT
,wobniar eht was eh
.denekcalb dlrow eht sa ssa sih otni gnisserp kcoc s’tar eht
,flesmih rednu dnah a teg ot deirt eH
,gniliar a debbarg eh litnu flesmih ediseb dnuora deporg eH
.siht od dluoc eH
?erofeb taht enod evah ti t’ndluow yhw neht tuB
,ybgur gniyalp efil sih sdneps eH
.ruoloc gnilbmur fo ynohpocac a neht
.erac t’ndid eh dna ,gnol woh wonk t’ndid eh
.eulb leets deppals sevooh siH
.cisum eht htiw emit ni yltfos meht gnikorts
.tnedifnoc dna lufyalp
,dewaffug esahC   .raef dna
,thgin lamron a nO
.eenk eno ot deppord esahC dna ,thgiew sih troppus ot deliaf gel thgir siH
.emit emas eht ta lla derrulb dna krad dna thgil ti gnivael
,neerg dna elprup dna der dna wolley
,tsol dah eh esoht fo thguoht esahC
evah dluoc gniht eht fi derednow esahC
.ecalp eht saw sihT
.flesti rednu sgel sti teg ot revo llor t’ndluoc tub
,noom tnaidar eht tsniaga detniuqs eH
…eulb thgirb fo elddup llams a saw ereht ,mih fo tnorf ni tuB
tnurg egieb a evag ynnub ehT
.moderob eht dnatsrednu dluoc esahC   .derob
.ti gnihcuot ylecracs erew yeht hguoht sa
ti guhc ot tuoba saw dna
.noom lluf eht morf thgirb gninihs llits
,knalb dekool taht llaw fo eceip a no ,neht dnA
,ediw delims dna mih ta dekool ehS
.devaeh stsehc rieht
,daeh sih evoba dehcaer
;pop aihcsuf a saw erehT
,tsehc sih ni mih tih gnihtemos tlef esahC neht tuB
.lwarc ot nageb esahC
.mih pots ot etal oot saw ti wenk esahC tub ,denrut ezah ehT
,ecnad ot nageb eH
,skcalc deruoloc-tsur ,gnilbmuts htiW
.diulf suoicerp fo dnik emos ylniatrec saw ti tub
.hcnup a gniydaer
,nwod saw esahC taht was neht tub
,moor eht ssorca gninihs sruoloc gnilriws eht htiw ,ereh nevE
.egrahc lluf ni llub a pots ot hguone ton saw taht tuB
.thgir ti dekcart t'ndah seye sih—
,esahC ta thgiarts detniop segde deggaj ehT
”eno neerg tahT“ ?niaga ti saw tahw
.wenk esahC ,rof gnithgif htrow gnihton saw erehT
gof eht hguorht thgir tnew tsif sih tub
.llaw eht ffo ecnuob kcilc nayc eht was dna
…taews dna reeb dlo fo ksum eht
.thgif siht niw ot hguone eb t'ndluow enola noitpmug tuB
.atnegam thgil ylralimis a ni dias esahC
.gnorw saw gnihtemoS
.wobniar eht fo ruoloc rehtona ees dluoc esahC tsiwt yreve ni
,ylwols ylgnisinoga yb tnew elbat hcaE
.niaga top reh otni dehcaer dna
.roolf eht ot detlob erew selbat eht dna ,devomer neeb dah sriahc eht llA
.despalloc eh dna
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,ton ro doolb ti llac ot rehtehw wonk t’ndid esahC  .gnihtemos
”gniS yretsyM eht hselF siH fO“
,dessap tnemom a retfA
.erom ecno erutaerc eht otni dna drawrof snroh sih gnivird
,tnemevap eht tih esahC
,mih dnuora roolf eht ot pord ti gnittel
.gel sih otni sregnif sih gud esahC
.taorht sih ni thguac traeh s’esahC
,sgum owt debbarg dna
,noitom kciuq a ni ,nehT
",retfa pit eht em evig ot esimorp uoy fi ylnO"
.llef eh sa ynnub eht gnippord ,despalloc esahC
.rood nepo na hguorht detnirps neht
hpmuirt fo tnemom a tlef esahC dna
dah ecaf s’ynnub eht erehw tuB
.esol dluow esahC
,dnoces a rof esahC deiduts eh ,yenom eht koot tar eht sA
.no dloh ot deganam esahC tub
,secaf—esle gnihtyrevE
,ytinummoc yrruf eht ni elbatrofmoc tsom sleef eh
.doom sih gnittif tsuj tsilacov eht fo lrans evissergga ,ypsar eht
gniyrrac sepip erew ereht dna
,bolb eht kcurts dah eH
,etihw dna eulb erew sdrow ehT
.nalp a dedeen eH
.gnidnats llits saw esahC tuB .yerg nrut dna
setunim 51 tuoba rof ti dekcart dah esahC
snroh sih no gut a tlef esahC
,tnemevap eht tsniaga fooh sih deppat eH
.tsehc sih no dexim yrreP dicA dna
.siht ekil ereh fo tuo teg ot gniog reven saw eH
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.roolfecnad eht dehcaorppa esahC
.ecaf sih no nirg live na dna
.deretaw seye sih dna
,ot pu saw gniht siht revetahW
.bolb yrebbulb eht otni ,tsrif nroh
.mih dniheb hguoc duol a draeh eH
.ereht elpoep desserdrevo tsom eht fo eno saw esahC ,tlik dna knat sih nI
,naorg deroloc-tsur a draeh esahC
,teef sih ot flesmih dellup dna
,ti otni noitartsurf dna regna sih lla tup eh
,saw esahC derit woh
.daeha telpord a ees dluoc esahC
,ylesolc dekool eH
,eros woh ees dluoc gniht eht hguoht sA
,eno tsrif eht sa drah sa tsuj mih tih tI
.gnitoof sih tpek eh tub
ecart tsetniaf eht tub gnihtyreve tuo gninword
.mih ees dluoc ti wenk esahC tuB
,elbbur eht ta gnirats ,ereht yal esahC
,thgim sih lla htiw ,nehT