pu wap rehto sih thguorb enilef eht ,detnuadnU
,niar eht otni depael nitsirK
,niaga gnirps ot delioc ehs sa tsuj tub
,doots dna detrons ailaT
.hsif dna staem ediR'"
.hcum denrael dna ,rehtona eno rof thguof
lla su sllet tcap ehT
,reh denioj nitsirK
'?ayuH fo ksa uoy od noob tahW .kaepS
'.skeew rof sdnalssarg eht ssorca uoy esahc dna nac I kcits tseggib eht dnif lliw I
reh dia ot serutaerc eht gnirb ot ediw dna raf nar
thgil fo smaeb gnizalb
,noziroh nretsew gniremmihs eht ot detniop ehS
si yrots s'yadot dnA
denrael serutaerc eht nehw syad eht litnu
.roolf htruof eht morf detfil
,sraeb ,snooccar ,eciM
.rehto hcae fo gnidnatsrednu ruo evorpmi ot emoh kcab egdelwonk ym erahs lliw I dna
.hteet wohs ot erus gnikam ,delims ailaT
,yad eht gnirud yks eht ni noom dna nus htob ees ew dna semitemos pu sehctac eh hguoht
seigolohtna ni derutaef neeb osla sah krow siH
,hcamots reh no ssarg yrd
.teef rieht htaeneb yltfos gnurps taht
.sduolc krad otni devlossid ti litnu rediw dna
?su kcatta uoy did yhw tsuj
,rehtorb reh fo daeha yats ot elba syawla nus eht
.ti edam ylraen uoy taht dna wolloh taht revo depmuj I gniht dooG
,elpoep ruoy tuoba nrael ot lanoitacude yrev si tI
.erutaerc elbaronoh na si nitsirK
rettil fo yrrulf a ni ffo hguod eht gnittuc ,detsug dniW
.erom elttil a dootsrednu dna
ebor yvaeh a erow tI
.hsalf a ni ffo saw ailaT '!nuR'"
'.yad eht fo naidraug sa ecalp reh ekat dna edisa reh worht dluow eh
,gnirps ot ydaer tac eht
.ailaT ,ti gnirahs rof uoy knahT
,elpoep ruoy rof pleh gnikees emoc evah uoY'" .swap reh desiar
tcap eht tsniaga llik ohw esohT
'.nerdlihc ,llew enod evah uoY'"
,thguoht eod eht ,secnatsmucric tnereffid nI
.ailaT naht rellat saw revo depoots neve dna
deremmilg ohw ,noom dna
'.dneirf doog a era uoY
,retal levart fo syad owT
,retsis sih naht lufituaeb ssel gnieb rof dehsinup gnieb saw eh taht gnileef
reh thguac eh nehw dna
.redro trohs ni meht yb nwod nrow eb dluow eh taht suoivbo saw ti tub
noitoved fo level tsehgih eht dehcaer evah taht rebmun rieht fo esohT
'.revir eht ot og ylekil dluow sliarT
,dias ehs reh dedia dah taht slamina eht fo hcae oT
hguoht ,sdnalssarg dehcrap eht
.uoy ot gnihton did eW
.setam-rettil yna sa esolc sa erew
,xofyerG ynoT yb mrotS eht emoC
,esaelp ,thgir llA
,dnuora denrut ehS
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikaK m'I
,noisnet sih tlef ehS
,dlrow eht fo sretae-ssarg eht fo lla ees ew erehT
,seldeen enip hguorht dniw eht naht reduol ylerab
.taorht sih deraelc nitsirK ,yllaniF
.dnoces a rof toN
,kcab erew srae sih
.dnuorg eht ot drows sih deppord eH
pu hctac ot elba saw nooM
,yldednahffo dias eh
.yerg htiw yks eulb eht gnirevoc
.tlep trohs reh fo tuo
'?kcub taht no efink ruoy desu evah yllaer
gnol neeb sah tI .stao
,eson sih desiar netsirK
',ton od I ,ton ro eurT'"
.ylbisiv detliw kle ehT
.eldnub eht ta deffins ehs sa
,niaga esor dniw ehT '.rebmemer dnA
,taps kle eht fo eno
hgiht eht ni drah mih dekcik ailaT erofeb
retteb hcum os era sredle ehT'" .dessarrabme
,nus taht dediced saw ti
dnuorg deraelc eht no kcab tas ailaT
.swap sih gnikat ,drawrof depmuj dna dehgual ehS
"'.won peels emos teg dna snoitseuq gniksa pots lliw I taht'"
--yeht taht wonk llA
.meht neewteb elttes ot riohc suovren a gniwolla emit siht
daerps ssarg fo aes eht ,ti dnoyeB
,nus eht fo noitatneserper a dehcteks dna
.drah gnipmup sgel gnol
slaog esoht deveihca evah uoy taht egduj I
!sniar ehT !ti did eW'"
.yenruoj eht gnirud erom hcum dnuof evah dna
sdrow detnarg eh
'.su fo llA'" .kcab neht
hcuorc a otni deppord ailaT erofeb deeps citnarf fo stnemom wef a ylno saw ylurt ti tub
.daeh sih koohs eH
.hguoht ,krad lluf s'ti erofeb tip erif a gid dluohs eW
,retsis sih hctac ton did eh elihW
,yks eht otni kcab esor ehs neht dnA
,kle eht ta deppans ehs '?uoy era ohW'"
.yrgna dna talf saw eciov s'nitsirK
.enif eb dluohs tI .pu tas dna
.daetsni egasiv yrgna na tub
,psirc no tuo dehcterts
slamina dehtoot-prahs eseht deksat dna
seert deppit-neerg eht ot revir eht morf pu gnihcterts dnarts yhsurb eht ssorc ot
.tserof eht deretne dah liart rieht erehw gnidnats sevlesmeht dnuof yeht ,delttes ti nehW
.tacbob eht ta tpmetta nwo sih ekat ot ni devom rehto eht dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
.drows trohs sih dnuora dehcnelc ton wap eht ni
.esir eht revo reep ot daeh reh detfil ailaT
,drah rekcatta reh tib ehS
rediw gnidaerps neht
.noitnetta dednamed tub
'.ailaT ,tuoba gniklat er'uoy tahw wonk t'nod I
,netsirK dna ailaT ,emit tsaL
dlrow eht fo serutaerc eht nehw dna
,ecaf reh ees reve ylno ew hguoht ,did ehs sa
.niar eht ni deggas dna
.efink reh gnihtaehs
.erutseg taht ni hteet sih fo hsalf eht yb
'!ereh era sniar ehT
.tsud eht ni serugif eht ot derutseg ailaT
.thguord ecaf osla ,srobhgien ruo dna egalliv ym ,eW'" '.uoy dnA'"
.dennalpnu dna thguosnU'" .tsehc eht ni meht fo hcae deppat ayuH
'!hO'" '--si tahW ?ailaT'"
.daeh reh koohs dna
,redduhs reh edam dna
,ailaT ta nwod delims eH
.hsub nroht taht ni ylluf dednal su fo eno dah elihw a etiuq rof ereh neeb evah dluow ew kniht I
'.em dnif nac yhtrow eht ylt'nereW'" .swap reh daerps
meht nopu dekool nuS
.gninrom eht ni revir eht ekam dluohs ew kniht I'"
,ailaT ta decnalg netsirK '.su pleh esaelP'"
,reh ees elpoep ruo sa
,setubirtta rieht was yks eht rehtom rieht dna
.ti deinapmocca won taht srehto eht dna
.noitarepooC .gnidnatsrednU'"
serutaerc gnuoy owt ehT ".hguoht
eb ll'ew neht dna
,ylimaf fo noitnem eht tA
.taorht s'kcub eht tsniaga tser ot pu edalb nwo reh evord ailaT
.ssarg fo elkcarc a htiw dnuorg ytsud eht otni gniggid sevooh ruof lla
.ecnarongi sih fo nrael ot desirprus demees ehS
'.emoc sniar eht taht ksa osla eW .stfig esehT
'!gniteem ylimaf A !ym
,oot kniht dluoc dna
.tac eht ta delims dna
.tcap nwo ruoy demrof evah owt uoY
.dlog tesnus otni denetfos thgil eht sa dnuora dereep netsirK ,desufnoC '?tahw A'"
,tacbob eht ot txen doots ehS ?I oD
ecaep ni evil ot thguos ohw eW
,nus eht dnuora rehtegot emac lla srehto ynam eht dna
,setam rieht dna srennid rieht dnif ot sgel ruof no nar lla
.yrots eht tuoba suoiruc ma I tuB
.suoiruc ,deksa eh ,esaelP
'.lla ta suovren ton ma I'"
stfig ralimis meht detnarg dna
,esir llams a dniheb devruc dna
.ssarg eht otni gnilwarps mih gnidnes
.ylthgils debrab er'yeht kniht I dna
kle erom owt esnes dluoc ailaT
.ssarg llat eht otni deraeppasid kle eerht eht litnu
.gninrom txen eht edis rehto eht ot egassap dedivorp reviR kaO eht fo hcterts ykcor A
redluob ot redluob morf gnignirps ailaT
,gnihtolc rieht delkceps spordniaR
.dneirf ym ,snisuoc ynam dna srehtorb redlo ruof evah I'"
!retae-taem yhtliF
'.oot ,eucser ym ot emac uoy ,lla retfA .ailaT ,uoy era sA'"
.tsap syad eerht swollef ruo fo eno dellik dna detnuh ohw sreredrum gnikees neeb evah ew ,retae-taem ehT
,elims a htiw dias dneirf reh ',ailaT'"
sehcac rieht dehcaer
fo trap lanif dna
.gnihtemos rednow od I tuB
hctaw ot denrut owt eht
.daeh sih koohs nitsirK
evisserpmi neeb evah dluow sreltna siH
.nialp eht ssorca deohce taht sraor gnilbmur yb tem saw lrans enilef yrgna na ,reh dniheB
,dehctaw owt eht sA
"?yaw yna ni uoy pleh ew naC
.etunim krad ,gnol a rof sgnidnuorrus rieht tuo dettolb ti elihw enola nitsirK dna ailaT tel ti emit sihT
sretae-tun dna ssarg eht tnuh ot
,netsirK ta dekool ailaT
htaerb peed a koot reed ehT
,elims llams a htiw dias netsirK
.uoy ot egdelp I sihT
,retsis sih naht ydoom dna devreser erom gnieb
.nageb ti sa ylkciuq sa detapissid ti tub
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ot ezag reh denrut neht
pu dehcaer ti yllaniF
,evol reh fo htmraw eht dna ecaf gniwolg reh htiw
,ew dna hsif dna retaw reh thguorb srettO
"'.erutan fo sterces eht denrael dna
'.erom gnihtemos dnA .riaf tnellecxE
,sedalb mils esoht fo eno dna
.yks eht ot ecaf sih denrut dna daerps smra
,rafa morf meht ta nwod gnikool morf dlrow eht fo serutaerc ynam eht wenk ehS
.setoyoc yb dellik saw nisuoc ruO
,nus eht denioj serugif llamS
,ecnalbmeser ylimaf eht was
,yks eht ssorca nus gnisahc syad sih lla dneps dluow eh taht deralced eh dna
,rehtona eno no desucof oot raf erew yehT
.snialp eht ssorca delruc tnecs elbakatsimnu nA .erac t'ndid ehS
.flesmih fo erac ekat ot evah
.kcab delims nitsirK '!ti did eW'"
,noisiced siht fo draeh eh nehW .srats eht dna
nrut ot reh degru
htaerb-esuap a ton
.meht raeh ylerar eW .desuap ehs tub
,tip erif a fo krow trohs edam
.srehto dna enizagaM taeH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioVehT
'.elpoep ruoy tuoba retae-taem sdrawkcab ,roop a etacude ot hsiw ton od uoy'"
ecaf ot ecaf teem ylerar yehT
.era uoy ereh dnA'"
gniworg eb ot hsub elbmarb a rof ecalp ylevol a tahW
,emas eht demmirt sreltna
,elzzird ydaets a otni denrut niar fo elknirps a
.hteet prahs dah ti sa gnol os tegrat eht ni detseretni elttil erew dna
tacbob eht ta redluohs reh revo dekool
.dereviuq doow fo htgnel eht elihw
tserof tsav eht otni derats htuoy owt eht dna reh denioj nitsirK
,sthgieh eht otni esor nmuloc krad a ,tserof eht morF
,stao deird ,daerbliart eniW'"
.uoy naht yltneiciffe erom meht kcart ot elba eb yam I
,xofyerG ynoT yb mrotS eht emoC
deronoh dah ehs taht serutaerc eht was eh
,ni syaw elttil a klaw tsuj dluohs ew spahreP
,sevooh reh devaw ehS
!hcuO--tsaf a era uoY
.ees dluoc eye eht sa raf sa
.sih tsniaga desserp redluohs reh
.sredle ruoy ton era sredle ruo'"
,erutuF yrruF eht dna
,meht htiw enog dah ecurt ysaenu nA
,evoba daerps sduolc eht sa
.denrael evah uoy tahw erahS
,denethgiarts nitsirK ".uoy
,bmilc ot ytiliba rieht
,kcab sih ffo gnilgnad dleihs llams a
.gnieb yna ro ,lerriuqs ,flow ,reed ,tac eb ew rehtehw ,rehtona eno htiw dlrow eht erahs dna
,tops eht no dnuora denrut ylraen ehS
sredro sih dewollof yeht dna
,ria eht ta gniffins
sehcnuah reh ot delttes ailaT
,stibbar gnipael gnol eht
'.ereh er'ew taht won rof kool ot yltcaxe tahw aedi on evah llits dna revir egral a dessorc
.elims deveiler a mih dehsalf ailaT
,yrgna emaceb noom
,repsihw a sa tuo emac eciov s'ailaT '?efil fo
,ecaf depparw s'nitsirK ta decnalg ailaT
.eciov s'kle eht morf deppird niats ehT
.kcatta ruo rof yrros ,hu ,ma I
.meht erofeb sllih hgih eht otni debmilc taht
'?ni og ew llahS'" '.raiL'"
tsew eht nI .erehT'" '?erehW'"
thgin eht fo naidraug eht emoceb dluow
.sgel reh ot txen tlenk ohw
ayuH'" '.ylbarimda
?won hteet prahs evah yeht esuaceb ylpmis erovinrac yna kcatta ew oD ?ton ew oD
.deretsiger rotpac reh fo tnecs eht
,dnuorg eht otni demmals dna redluob eht revo deltsihw raeps A "--si tahW
.seciov peed fo elbmur teiuq lanoisacco eht dna
.ylteiuq deddon eod ehT
.niaga mih htiw tcennoc yllufepoh dna
'.gnineve eht rof deb reh ot gnidaeh ,nus eht si
.meht dedrawer ehs
.ylsuoiruc tac eht dedrager dna
,kcab dekcud eH '!eyA'"
.nitsirK ,uoy knahT
.morf emoc elpoep ym erehw fo gnihton draeh ev'I tub
,revir eht raen ffo os ro yad a ,nwot rieht yal
em tel ,emoC'" .mra sih desu eh sa
.drawpu detniop ailaT '!kooL'"
.snevaeh eht hguorht reh gniwollof
tsae eht ot ereht dnA
,dias ailaT ',kniht I'"
.meht erofeb doots taht erugif eht ta derats yehT
gnuoy saw dlrow eht nehw syad eht nI'" .nageb dna
klaw 'stnemom wef a tub saw tI
.daerps llams a ot nwod demmirt neeb ton yeht dah
.eralf slirtson sih was ailaT
.niaga llef ecneliS
.yrruFoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
gniniarts ,desiar srae ,ezorf ehs erehT
kool resolc a koot ailaT
.yadot evil ew taht
ti gniypucco serutaerc fo oirt ehT
,delwarps tseroF dnebkaO eht ,ti ssorcA
eht ot eldnub reh tuo dleh hguod ehT
.yad eht gnirud dlrow eht nopu nwod kool dna
,tcap eht fo retibra gniniamer tsal eht sa dna ,laog ruo saw hcuS
,detelpmoc si ksat ruo ecno ,tcaf nI
,sevooh reh gnipsalC
'.rethgif a etiuq er'uoY
mrots gnignirb-efil eht sa
.sllihtoof eht gnirevoc neerg fo teprac tsav a
,llef ecneliS !uoy fo llA
.yaw taht sleef tI
meht nopu dekool ehs dna
.tnelis llef dna daeh reh dewob ailaT
,wollahs skool tI
.dnif thgim yeht dnuos yna rof
.drows eht fo hsals deniart a htiw
efil fo revig eht ,nus eht
.keehc s'etivres eht ssorca skram lellarap taen ruof tfel dna
depmuls ruf kciht sih sa dehctaw ailaT
,tnecs taht no ni deknoh ehs ,daetsnI
',hO'" "?morf emoc elpoep ruoy erehw tuoba seirots yna erahs stseirp ruoy oD
.taht sdrawot redrah nar ehS
,wollef sih htiw dnats ot pu ylwols depmil kcub driht ehT
,klE yzarC yb dekcatta
,noom eht ,rehtorb reh si
,ereht tuo tnemevom eb ot demees ereht tub
.ruf rieht dettod
.eod eht rof nrecnoc on desuac stniop prahs esoht taht trofmoc reh fo erusaem a saw tI
.ailaT ,yrots lufrednow a si tahT
"'.sdranni sti morf dlrow eht otni eerf gnarps elpoep ruo fo tsrif eht dna tros emos fo lamina yerp a trapa erot tnuh eht fo sdrol tsrif eht taht dlot er'ew'"
.niaga ecno mih gnipacse rof gnilbis sih etipsed dehsiw dna
.detrons tacbob eht
.noitautis eht etaulave dna nrut neht
.ecrof rehto ro doolf dessap-gnol emos yb nialp eht no tfel
,regna ni pu deffup ruf ,nitsirK tub
.hsiw uoy fi wonk I tahw uoy llet dluoc I
.emit a rof tser ot dnuorg ot emac daetsni dna
,emas eht si ksat ruO
,sremmus ynam rof
'?gel ruoy parw dluohs ew kniht uoy oD
.ailaT ,ekoj t'noD'"
.seye ediw htiw gnirats reh htaeneb kle eht
.dnuora dna pu gnippans daeh ,ffo ekorb eh
.secaf rieht no tnedive tsurtsid rieht
.delims reed ehT ".yadot did ew sa
ecaf s'raguoc ylredle eht ssorca daerps elims A'"
.ssalg denettalf fo edam gniraelc a ni saw ehs ylneddus dna
.ynomrah ni rehtegot evil ot
,srehtorb ylbaborp ,eerht esehT
.noinapmoc reh ta dekool ailaT '.era ew ereH'"
nihc reh dehctarcs dna
.seye sih fo tuo ruf gnihsurb
,doolb fo egnit yreppoc eht gnitsat
,yrgna dna talf erew seye siH
llew sa teef owt no klaw ot rewop eht nevig saw hcaE .esuom ot raeb
.kle taht did uoy ekil nwod meht kconk nac uoy
,stac rellams dna taerg eht ,sexof eht oT
raguoc tneicna ehT
.ecarbme detsuahxe na ni rehtegot llef yeht litnu
.redluohs s'dneirf sih no wap a yal ot revo denael dna yltfos delkcuhc nitsirK
,tac retrohs eht ta ylediw delims dna
,ecar sseldne eht fo yraew emaceb nus yad eno tub
,nikrej rehtael deddap a erow eH
.lla uoy knaht I dna em ot ecivres sselfles ruoy hguorht htrow taerg ruoy nwohs evah uoy ,dias dna
.yllacitegolopa deggurhs eH
senip rellams wef tsrif eht tsaP
dnoces eht saw sihT ".ssarg
tnemom a ylno detsal yniturcs reH
,htmraw sih fo erahs ton did tub
.ti did eW .did ew ,seY'"
,od ew fI'" .detrons nitsirK ".hguoht
tnedive ssenippah sih
tacbob eht dehsup ehS '.taht ta kool
.em rof gnithgif roF'" '?tahw roF'"
?retsis dna rehtorB'" .denworf netsirK
,tnecs doolb eht htiw delgnim
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,gnihtyna fo hcum ees ot tluciffid ti edam ssarg llat ehT
,syad ruof rof em htiw gnilevart neeb sah tac siht ,lleW
.pots reven dna eelf dna
.gnihton llems I'"
,tac blub dna reed a
,devirra eh erofeb snevaeh eht ni ligiv reh ot denruter ohw
.ti dniheb gninosaer eht ees ylniatrec nac I
,tsael ta tnemom eht rof ,dluow nitsirK
,ybraen erehwemos ssorc ot ecalp wollahs a eb dluohs erehT
'.raey eht fo syad tsegnol dna tsetrohs eht no elat eht su llet sredle ruO'"
fo traP laniF dna dnoceS ehT
,wolloh neddih eht ni
,bro gnizalb eht gnidnuorrus
.ssarg yrd gniltsur ezeerb eht fo dnuos eht tub gnihton saw ereht tnemom a roF
,uoy llet lliw I ,thgir llA'"
.eod eht ta derats kle eerht llA
.riaf hcus dah evah I ecnis
,ailaT ?netsirK ,spahrep ,reltneg elttil A !hcuO
.hguoht ,thginot melborp a evah yam ew ,ybraen srotaderp erom era ereht fI
?retae-taem eht htiw levart uoY
.nitsirK ot denrut eH .uoy fo htoB
.erom siht uoy tnarg I taht roF
.revir eht lellarap dna nrut neht
.pleh ym reffo yldalg lliw I ,stsirotom eseht kees llits uoy fi
evaw a ni dellor
.dessap erew reh rof stoor dna selbategev
.hcrep reh morf nwod kcab gnibmilc erofeb thgis fo tuo erew yeht litnu detiaw llits ailaT tub
.emoh yaw ruo no nitsirK htiw nruter lliw I dna
.yletades yb dellor kao eht ,daehA
,ylralimis tcaer thgim ehs
.eveels reh deggut netsirK litnu
dnal eht fo ytnuob dna serutaerc eht ffo evil dna
.tser reh ni reh draug dna
ruopnwod eht ni gnilriwt owt ehT
sseniraew reh was yehT
.swollef rieht ot thgieh ni resolc tsael ta eb ot ezis retaerg nevig erew rellams eht dna
.meht fo lla s'taht kniht I'"
.ylthgils dexaler eH
snroht eht fo eno ta deirrow eH
'.yar eht deen srehto ynam dna egalliv ruO
sessarg fo elttar eht raeh dluoc ehs
rekcits dezis ylevisserpmi eht gniggut yllanif
.lavirra reh eciton t'ndid
,sroirraw owt eht tsniaga
,elbissop sa ylkciuq sa regnad eht morf yawa teg ot reh dlot tcnitsnI tub
.reh dnuora depparw taht smra gnorts fo riap a otni thgir
,niaga ecno thgilf otni depael dna
.emoc ton evah sniar ehT
'.t'ndluoc I ,on ,on ,hO
,esruoc fo ,selat era ereht ,llew ,hU
,tnelis llef ehs niagA
.llew eviL .ti ekaT
?etoyoc a ekil kool nitsirK seoD
syaw eht nrael ot srotsecna ruo gnivael
.dessih dna meht neewteb deppets
.nitsirK dna ailaT dlot dah yeht
.od sporc dna ssarg eht sa tsuj niar deen slamina ruO
ezag dedooh krad ehT
?erutaerc a hcus dnefed ton dluow uoY
,retto ot lerriuqs
.niap ni mra sih gnidloh daetsni ,reh derongi ohw
.ecioVehT ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
'?uoy t'nod ,worromot ylthgils nwod wols ot deen ew kniht I'" .deredduhs ailaT ".hsub
,kle eerht eht ta
,syar on htiw eno siht
.seye reh dellor ailaT
.tnemom gnol a rof meht fo hcae ta gnirats
.erif llams a dah yeht
dleihs a gnidloh hcae
,tsrif ta niht-eldeen
.tacbob eht ot denrut ehS '.uoy knaht I
ecneicS ?sliart yna ees uoy oD'"
stcA namuhnI ekil
.tleb sih no drabbacs a ni detser edalb mils gnol a dna
.dleihs eht no thguac ti evah ot ylno
?selat esoht llet sredle ruoy oD
nruter ni yawa edalb eht deppals nitsirK
,hcum oot ssarg eht tpursid ot ton luferaC
,ayuH ta dekool htuoy ehT'"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
srovaedne emit-thgin sih morf wenk eh taht serutaerc eht nopu dekool eh ,hU .ylsuovren
,yarps gnilkcirp eht morf ecaf reh gnirevoc ,decniw ailaT
.taorht s'kcub eht tsniaga thgit efink reh gnipeek ,dednamed ailaT
,tnecs eht fo ecruos eht deraen ehs sa pu esor
redluob rehtona sdrawot gnilbmarcs
slerriuqs gnibmilc-tsaf ehT
.stfig eseht gnirb I
nitsirK tfel dah ehs erehw sdrawot kcab yaw reh krow dluoc ehs taht tnaem tiusrup oN
redluob eht pota morf dehctaw yehT .noos dna
,prahs dna yreppoC
thgin dna yad eht gnirud dlrow eht fo ecaf eht deklaw taht srehto eht dna
,hO'" .yks eht ot dekool dna
,tcap eht edistuo enog sah ohw eno
tcap taerg eht detaerc tsrif ohw ew yb tes slaog eht era esehT .pihsdneirF
,dnuorg ytsud eht no hcteks reh ni bro rehtona dedda ailaT
,luaP dna fooH '!rehtegoT
.revo egakcap eht dednah eH
,rehto hcae neewteb etacinummoc ot retteb eht ,sdrow fo tfig eht uoy tnarg I
,sgnikram ralimis
.tserof ym si sihT .ayuH ma I'"
-eciov peed taht htiw eh a ylniatrec saw ti rof--eh
hctap krad a htiw deniats saw redluohs eno dna
.sretae-taem eht dna sretae-ssarg eht neewteb
thguord a ot rewsna eht tuo kees ot tseuq a ni snoinapmoc ylekilnu sevlesmeht dnuof
'.ereh emoc ot ssarg fo aes eht ssorca yenruoj ruoy dewollof dna deen ruoy desnes evah I
.htob meht ot derutseg ehS .desufnoc
,elddim s'kle eht drawot nopaew nwo sih evord dna
.reh morf yawa gnivom ssarg eht ni elppir a
.noitaroda rieht tlef dna
.yoj htiw reh deteerg dna wenk yeht dna
.ezeerb eht ni gniltsur ssarg yrd sti
rehtegot evil ot
.ecaf desirprus eht otni detuohs ehs !rednerruS
,hguoht ,sevlesruo tcetorp tsum eW .doots
no tnew ecar ehT
.dnik ruoy fo ton si taht erutaerc yna gnikcatta ylpmis naem ton dluohs taht dna
.selpoep ruoy dna uoy nopu htmraw dna thgil ym tsac reverof lliw I ,egnahcxe nI
retaw fo ylppus suoicerp reh morf deppis ehS
4102 rof tsetnoc gnitirw ylraey tsriF yaR eht ni pu-rennur a saw yrots sihT
.tsehc sih nwod ylwols gnidaerps
,retsis sih truh ot yaw a sa
,ikaK yb uoy rof daer
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.uoy tsurt nac ew esoppus I .thgir llA
nitsirK sdrawot gnignul
.seot s'nitsirK morf
.gnihtemos uoy hcaet lliw tcap eht yb sevil ohw erutaerc elbaronoh na htiw emit emos gnidneps spahreP
.kcab dooh eht werd dna
.ecnelis ni tnemom a rof meht ta derats
'.rehtona eno htiw thgif yllanrete naht rehtar
.redle elbaegdelwonk dna esiw O .deergA
,yad eht fo rotcetorp eht eb dluow
.demranu saw eh wohs ot desiar sevooh
dekcatta dah ehs kle ehT
,deen fo emit reh ni dia rieht rof dnA
.nus remmus eht fo taeh eht morf reffus sporc ruO'" .raguoc
,ni gud llew era snroht eht tub ,seigolopA
.emit taht ni rehtona eno tub gnihton nees evah ew dna
.nus eht dnuora serugif eht ot derutseg eH ?ti si tahW
'.dedeen fi thgif a pu tup nac ew tub ,ythgilf mees yam raeD
,redluob eht nwod kcab gnilbmarcS
,reredrum a kees uoy fI
kcab dellup ailaT
werg yeht sa tuB
.xofyerG ynoT yb
sehtolc reh morf seldeen gnihsurb ,delbmurg ehS
,kcab delbmuts roirraw ehT
,nerhterb rieht dna ,setoyoc eht ,slesaew eht
hguorht tseroF dnebkaO eht sdrawot levart owt eht
thgirpu gniklaw dna
.tcap eht wollof sretae-taem lla ton tuB
,rehtegot nur evah uoY
.yaw emos ni reh dedia hcae dna
,reh drawot pets niatrecnu na koot kcub dednuow ehT
htaerb a koot ehS
woleb lla htiw ecnaillirb reh gnirahs
.niaga ecno thgilf a roolf tserof eht tes taht lrihw suoiciv a
!hcuO .delbmurg ehs
htaehs sti morf efink reh koot ailaT sa pu tas netsirK
,reed detoof-teelf eht
gnicniw dna rewols gnivom
.timda ot sekil eh naht regnol rof noitcif yrruf gnitirw neeb s'ohw
,ylniatrecnu rehto hcae ta dekool kle fo oirt ehT
?ti t'nseod ,tif ot smees ti ,niaga ,lleW .huH
eldnub eht detpecca ayuH
,tsav a ni sevlesmeht dnuof yeht
.no os dna ,miws ot ,hsif ot
.detlit daeh siH '.uoy knahT'"
,flac s'reed eht otni kcuts
.yldab delb taht hctarcs a tsuj
stnemom wef a nI
netsirK dna ailaT
.ssarg fo aes eht ssorca
.reed elbaronoh na tsurt lliw uoy spahrep neht ,tacbob elbaronoh na tsurt ton od uoy fI
ssom dna seldeen dlo htiw deteprac ,tserof tneicna
.kcab sih no fooh a yal dna
,etelpmoc tsum ew eno si ksat ruo tuB .uoy knahT
noitcerid taht ni erehwemoS
.daeh sih koohs dna
,og reh tel dna--depley-
decils saw cinut enif sih ydaerlA
,resolc deppets erugif eht sa etum doots
.swollef sih ta gnicnalg ,dias kle eht fo eno ,lleW ".uoy
.dnuora teef lareves rof ssarg gniraelc
.derahs dah retsis sih esoht ot
,erovinrac morf erovibreH stcetorp taht tcap eht rednu gniviL
,seert eht sa tneicna sa demees eciov ehT
'?eb ot emac ew woh fo yrots eht wonk ton uoy oD'"
,rebmem ylimaf a egneva ot gnikees erew
.segalliv rieht revo nellaf sah taht
dewohs swalc prahs dna
uoy dluoW'" .desuap nitsirK
.ylsuoiruc tacbob eht ta daeh reh detlit ailaT
'!dekrow tI !dekrow tI'" .niar drah
?eM'" '.ti llet esaelP
,noom eht rehtorb reh dna
deraeppasid nus ehT
nwo sih gnidloh saw tacbob ehT
slirtson reh otni tperc doolb fo llems eht
"'.eb ot deen ew erehw ot nekat dna ecrof larutannu emos yb pu tpews eb ,erus m'I ,lliw ew ,tserof eht ni era ew ecno dnA'" ,kcab delims ehS
.nialp eht ffo welb ezeerb looc a dna delkcarc gninthgiL
.seiceps rieht hcae gnivig serutaef hguor
.gnirb uoy tnemgduj tahw evresed
,ecafrus s'dlrow eht no gnitser saw nuS elihw taht dlot era eW
.htaerb a koot reed ehT .esruoc fo ,hO
,ylleb eht ni mih kcurts elissim nat A
,ecaf sti revoc ot desiar dooh eht
mrotS eht emoC yojne esaelP
.ygolohtna ytirahc s'raey txen eht ni deraeppa dna
,ytinrete na ekil demees nur reH
.edisni dereep dna
,redluob a no dehcrep nitsirK "'.tserof eht ni
gnissih enilef dna stuohs yrgnA
,snroca dna stun reh thguorb dna
.meht gnikcatta saw revetahw fo raelc delbmarcs dah nitsirK taht stseggus tahT !dooG
.ti morf gnitaidar
.ereht tog reven eH
,thgilerif gnirekcilf eht ni thguac
ecnatsid raen eht nI
',sediseB'" '.yawa raf os dna
,stfig tsetaerg rieht htiw tfel saw seiceps hcae tuB
.serutaerc detalernu yleritne gnikcatta tub
.tserof eht fo ytuaeb dna ega eht yb detnuad
.egde s'revir eht ot ylraen dehcaer taht
.nigeb ot reh rof denoitom ohw
.htiw dnetnoc ot taeh remmus eht dnoyeb sregnad rehto era ereht
.dnal yrd dehcaer ehs litnu
.tnangidni dna deniap saw
,syad evif rof gniklaw neeb ev'eW'" '?suovreN'"
.tcap eht swollof nitsirK .delrans ehs ,seY
reh dniheb tuohs s'kle ehT
,hsad a otni dehcnual eod ehT
.meht erofeb dnab ediw gnirettilg a emoceb dah reviR kaO eht
'?ew lliw ,wonk reven lliw eW'"
".dega eht dna nerdlihc ot sretsam esoht fo kaeps yeht esruoc fO'"
ydaets a ot ereht morf dna
'--s'teL .aedi dooG'"
,hgual uoy fi tub
.yrassecen leef uoy woh meht htiw laed ot thgir lla evah uoy neht
.redluohs sih morf cinut nrot eht werd dna tis ot
.tac fo tnih a dna
.ni degagne erew yeht ecnad yldaed eht dna
.sgniht yksep eseht evomer pleh ot elttil a swalc ym esu ot deen I .luferaC
.sgniht hcus od nac ohw sretsam fo kaeps netfo stseirp ehT
on daeh reh koohs ehS
.edalb sih dehtaehs eh sa neve detcarter swalc sih dna
.mih dekcik dah ehs erehw mraerof sih ta debbur eh "!hcuO