.niaga deredduhs ailaT'"
'?reed a htiw pu peek nac uoy rehtehw ees ew llahS'" .dennirg ehs
tserof tneb-kao eht ,neerg llud
.elpoep rieht rof pleh gnikees meht fo htob
,htuos seson rieht detniop owt ehT
,yas ton od seirotsih eht ,wonk ton od I
serutaerc gnuoy owt eht sa
,ssarg eht otni delttes
.doots dna ssarg fo etib tsal eno koot ailaT
.ria eht ta gniffins ,drawrof deppets notsirhC
,depraw owt eht sa llet ot seirots fo erahs sih dah eh
,ssarg eht gninnacs seye
,noitpircsed reh ta delknirc ecaf sih ',sorU'"
.ffo reh nees dah egalliv eritne ehT
,meht evoba daerps snevaeh eht gnihctaw
'.seof ton ,sdneirf sa retae-ssarg a edisgnola gninnur ,em htiw tespu yrev eb dluow yeht esruoc fO'"
4102 tsetnoc gnitirw ylraey tsriF niaR eht ni pu-rennur a saw yrots sihT
.ylsuoiruc revo gnikool
.ezorf serutaerc htob dna
'.notsirhC ,thgin dooG'"
.mih htiw efas eb ylekil dluow ehs ,llew
.tnemom gnol a rof rehto hcae ta derats serutaerc gnuoy owt ehT
,stserof eht ta daeha dekool ailaT
.gnihcnurc tnatsnoc siht tpecxe ,lufecaep
'?sdrol eht ekil serutaerc yna ot kool dnik ruoy oD
,thgirpu tohs srae
.egalliv eht fo htuoy eht morf
yaw eno ylno saw ereht dnA
.rennur lufrewop a ,gnorts ,eht-eyl ,llaT
'.deednI'" '.ddo si tahT'"
.snosaer nwo reh rof su htiw erusaelpsid sesserpxe nus eht semitemos dnA'"
eson reh detfil ailaT
,deriuqni ehs '?ksa yam I fi ,dnuob uoy era erehW'"
.peels gnignirb yllanif
'.ebircsed uoy yaw eht ni ton ,hO'"
.dias evah srotsecna eht woH
,sredrob eht gnola esoht yltsom tiebla
'?sretae-ssarg rehto eht dna
.neerg thgil fo hctap llams a dnuof ehs
'.tnuh eht fo drol eht ot emit rieht nevig
',hguoht ,tsaf dna gnorts kool uoY'"
.taeh eht fo sleeh eht no emac ylbairavni taht sretniw dloc eht hguorht
',taht sllet tsedle eht tsael ta
.yliraw dellac ehs '?uoy era ohW'"
.tcatnoc tcerid hcum tneverp ot trapa hguone raf erew sregalliv eht tub
,tacbob eht ta dekool ailaT
.sdnalssarg gnillor eht ssorca ylisae gniggoj ,niaga nar yehT
.esoppus I ,sredle eht ,lleW'"
'.gninaem ruoy wonk I'"
,ria eht ta gniffins
'.hguone elbapac eb dluow I kniht I
'.tnuh eht fo stseirp eht yb dna
elbisiv gnimoceb srats fo gnilknirps eht ta gnirats ,dehgis dna
,ecnef a gnisuac rof ezigolopa I'" .gninethgiarts
,sllih gnitaludnu ssorca ecnatsid eht otni daerps
',ecneirepxe ym ni suoiruc syawla era raeD'"
,eladnovA fo sllih kcab eht nI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikaK m'I
,taeh s'nus eht morf neddih yltrap dnuorg fo dlof a nI .desiar-eson
dna stcudorp rehto dna loow rof edart eW'"
.dnatsrednu I tahT'"
.tnemom a detarebiled ailaT ".ylefas
esira taht seiretsym dna sregnad eht ecaf yeht woh dna
.desum tacbob eht
,kcap eht yb devil eh fi dnA
tsud fo ffup hcae ,ssarg yrd-enob fo hcnurc hcae
.evoba nus remmus hgih eht morf
.deknilb eh '?yllaeR'"
'.sbreh dna doof gnirehtag
'.stac ew naht ecnarudne erom raf evah reed kniht I'"
,uoy knaht ,hA'" '.gnihsiruon
.ylhsrah taps notsirhC'"
.tsae eht ot segalliv morf semitemos seirots raeh ew
egalliv ruoy morf spahreP'"
,tuo dnif lliw uoy tub
',eseht ekil scirbaf enif teg eW
.stserof eht eb thgim taht egnit ycips thgils a
.tlob ot detnet elcsum yreve
,tnasaelp yrev eb tsum yehT'"
'.ereh tuo enola rehtar gnileef saw I ,tsenoh eb oT
,dneirf wen reh gnissap
elpoep ym rof tnuh eht detarbelec stseirp eseht erofeb dnA'"
?dekcap neeb dah tahW
.deffins dna elzzum reh detfil ailaT
.emoc od sredart ,sey tuB'"
'?sredle stseirp eht erA
.tiusrup ni ffo tes ehs
,tsrif ecnelis eht ekorb ailaT
gnisiar srae detfut
,dexaler raed ehT
,seye enivres htiw dekcol seye enilef
',neppah gniht ralimis a dah eW'"
,ssam krad a no tser ot gnimoc
.ylesolc erom dednelb eromhtuoS dna eladnovA fo stnediser eht taht esnes erom edam ti erehw
nirg ediw a htiW
,yad a rof gniklaw neeb dah ailaT .yellaV kaO fo
.selbuort derahs rieht ot noitulos a kees yeht sa
ksat siht hsinif ot deen I tsrif tub
.thguoht ailaT ,ecnedicnioc a fo hcum oot saw taht woN
tsomla neeb sah teiuq ehT
tsud fo ffup a yb deinapmocca saw ti semitemoS
.wolloh eht fo tuo eod eht dewollof notsirhC ".gnihcnurc
.saw eh tahw saw taht rof
,retaw fo pis a deredisnoc ehS
niaga deppirt ylraen eh dna
,htrof dna kcab dael eht gnidarT
?stseirp on evah uoY'" ?stseirP'"
,yad eno ebyaM'" .deggurhs ehS
.detcepxenu gnihtoN
dluoc ew spahreP'"
'.tserof dnebtuO'"
stcA namuhnI ekil
.em dlot tseirp eht os ro ,tnuH eht fo droL eht ot enirhs a ot og ylekil I taht wonk I tuB'" .deunitnoc neht
'.gnihtolc tnellecxe
,sruof lla no ylisae gnipol tacbob eht ,dennirg notsirhC
'.stnuh lufsseccus naht rehtar
mrotS eht emoC .yojne esaelP
'.yenruoj emas eht gnikam ma I
.daeha tserof gniworg eht sdrawot ,depol netfo dna
.mron eht morf raf llits saw gnidnelb hcus
dniw eht fo noitasnes eht gniyojne
tsud eht hguorht fooh a deffucs ehs
,tnew yeht sa enilef eht dehctaw ailaT
.kcab reh no deirrac ailaT eldnub eht otni ylluferac depparw dna ,secips ,sbreh ,daerb ,staO
sdreh yhtlaeh ,egral hguorht
',peehs desiar dah ylnO'" '.taeM'"
,ffo gnitsud ,ylwols doots tI
.ynapmoc tnasaelp eb ot devorp notsirhC
,sretae-taem fo noitalupop retaerg eht dima ytefas rof dehsilbatse neeb dah srehto dna ,slerriuqs ,reed fo segalliv erehw
'?gnorw gnihtemos sI'" .detlit daeh
'?elpoep ruoy rof snoitarbelec dna seinomerec eht stcudnoc ohW
.erofeb deneppah dah tahw derebmemer sredle eht tub ,yrd siht enog dah ssarg eht ecnis sraey ynam neeb dah tI .no deirrac dna
.yawa sedirts ytnewt emos deldduh
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dnebsorU ot etubirt a gnidnes
.egalliv eht pleh ot yaw emos em hcaet ,terces eht em llet
daerb drah eht fo etib a koot ailaT
.dnuob lufrewop eno ni wolloh eht fo tuo depael ehs dna
kniht I'" .rehtona eno htiw gnola dettort dah yeht
.taem nwo sih eta notsirhC elihw detreva seye reh tpek dna
.trac a gnillup setoyoc eerht dah eh dna
'.lworp eht no llits sretnuh fo skcaP
'?taht llems uoy oD'"
'.erahs ot emoclew er'uoy tub
.epyt evitcetorp eht yltcaxe ton saw notsirhC
.llaw enots dlo eht ni
deeps fo dnik taht ta levart nac ew fi
dekwauqs netsirK
.kcab sih revo gnuls kcap eht yalpsid ot
,deleviws daeh siH
noitceles reh ta dellirht neeb dah stnerap s'ailaT
?eb taht dluow ohw tuB'"
.revo saw noitasrevnoc eht detseggus taht enot a htiw dna
s'ailaT .ybraen spmuht gnihtemoS
',seitic eht morf egalliv ruoy ot yaw rieht edam evah sredart yas uoY'"
,egalliv eht del ohw eod tneicna eht ot gnidroccA
'.lla ot edart rof sniarg dna slamina doof htob esiar sremraf ruO'"
gnixaler erom ti dnuof ailaT tub
.erusopmoc sih gnirevocer erofeb
,ikaK yb uoy rof daer
.flesreh deksa ehs ,eb ti dluohs yhw tuB
gnirps fo dellems tI
.tsiaw eht ta detleb triks dna trihs elpmis a
.ailaT ,thgin dooG .seY'"
.rotaderp a ekil ,llew
ailaT '?uoy era ohW'"
.esoppus I ,ralimis gnihtemos ,llew
.snialp eht ssorca daerps thgin sa
evah ohw elpoep gnuoy er'yeht semitemoS .semitemoS'"
.emac ti llaftoof hcae htiW .elbapacseni
mih fo dniwpu elttes ot dnuora devom ehs sa dehctaw notsirhC'"
,delims eh ',dooG'" '.eerga I
.sdrow sih deredisnoc dna
yllacimoc tsomla gnimaerts stfut rieht ,dekrep srae sih
?egnellahc a taht sI'"
.devas eb lliw ew dna
deklaw ailaT os dnA
.dewehc ,derettahs
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
.enilef a saw eh tub
,eb dluow ti emussa I
.triks trohs reh gnihtooms dna seye reh no gnittauqs
,srae dekrep reh ssorca gniwolb
.notsirhC si eman ym ,mU'"
,enilef a htiw gninnur ,saw ehs ereH
.dias dah redle eht ,eciohc laedi na saw ehS
.edis eno ot dekool ehs dna
.ylthgil delkcuhc eH
.nwod ylluferac etubirt reh gniniatnoc kcap eht gnilttes ,dias eod eht
'.ecalp emas eht ot gniog eb dna shtap ssorc dluow ew taht ddo smees tsuj tI'"
.sniatnuom eht ssorca seitic dna snwot regral eht htiw ylraluger sedart egalliv ruO'"
.no deunitnoc dna
.daeh reh koohs ehS
hgual a htiw mih fo daeha dellup elod eht nehw
,deeps fo tsrub a no tup dna
.suoivbo saw esirprus reH'"
'.ecap ym ot pu era uoy fi eeS
,evoba morf gnitnuh ruo revo hctaw dna
sehtolc enif ni desserd eH .lerriuqs a
.retniw eht rof doof on
,pets hcae htiw dnA
.dees ot kcab gnillaf dna gnimoolb
.tuo smeti emos werd dna kcap-
htaed dna enimaf
.yb esolc morf tnes srotaderp eht erongi ot
',syad erom owt ni stserof eht hcaer yam ew
,detseggus notsirhC '?rehtegot levart
'.ti fo dir teg ot dekoms ylroop
.gnilkcarc eht dima repsihw a
'.esruoc fO'" .deddon dna
,srehto morf raf os ereh gnieb tub
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.egalliv eht tfel dah ehs nehw sa
tseretni ni dehctaw lla yehT
,slufhtuom ffo tib ehs sa tsriht reh dekcils dna erutsiom dna
raey eht rof tsevrah ruo fo noitrop a mih evag sredle ehT
.dniheb meht evael t'nac I .ylimaf ym
,yks sselduolc eht ot derutseg ailaT
,tort gnitae-dnuorg a otni gnikaerb
,pu kcab tas tac ehT
,ekil noitanigami reh ta tib dna dewalc ti dna
',ereht revo ffilctrohS morf m'I
,esle gnihtyreve ekiL
'.og ot noitareneg 4-tcaP eht ot deerga sredle ruO
'.detset gnieb m'I spahreP
.doof-liart nwo ym evah I'"
.esnopser ni detnurg notsirhC
ecaf sih desiar tacbob ehT
.sdnalssarg gnillor eht ssorca
.ylbatius dias ehs ',dnatsrednu I'"
.yltneuqerfni yrev klof ytic
.egalliv ym ni tnuh eht fo tseirp a dah syawla
.wolloh eht otni yaw sih edam llits eh tub
.deggurhs notsirhC
'?ot og uoy od tahW'"
'.llew sa ksat ym evah I
.daeha devom enilef eht sa detuohs ehs ',yeH'"
sekam dna ssertsmaes a si rehtom yM .sdoog ruo roF'"
ytirepsorp su evig
noitareneg ot noitareneg morf nwod dessap seirotS
,efil rof nus eht ot kool eW'"
dnuorg eht raen ssarg fo sklats ffo deppilc yltaen enilef eht sa
sremmus gnol eht tuoba
sesnes reh decrof dna
.cinut sih ot derutseg eh
'.resolc emoc I ,yhW .retaw detnec I'"
,tnassecni saw dnuos ehT
ssarg yrd fo aes eht ,daehA
,ehs naht retrohs sehcni emos saw eH
.kcap sih ni kcab meht tes dna
,delleviws daeh reH
'.ereh revo tis lliw I ,llew ,tuB'"
,yllacitahpme dias notsirhC ',erom yna toN'"
'.kcap eht stcepser enoyreve dna
'.yawa levart fo sruoh ynam llits sah tserof ehT .peels dluohs eW'"
sredael ruo yb tuo tes swal eht gnikaerb era segalliv esoht dnA'"
serutaerc owt ehT
.sniar eht gnirb ot
,gnitsevrah dna gnitnalp htiw pleh ot em deen yehT
kao eht ot htuos ,htuos oG
'.yaw taht detalosi etiuq si egalliv ruO
evah I'" .deggurhs notsirhC'"
,seitic eht ni rehtegot devil yerp dna rotaderp taht
,derettum tacblub eht '!skcor diputS'"
kcab denael ailaT
sllihtoof ssorca delwarps taht
.tnuomarap si noituac
.taht em llet ton dluoc redle ehT
',emit eht fo hcum dnuora htuoy ruo fo tser eht dnuora gnieb ot desu m'I'"
.ygolohtna ytirahc s'raey txen eht ni deraeppa dna
.evoba nus gnizalb eht fo taeh eht dna
.eladnovA fo ecnirP eht ot xat a yap ot saw ti dias dna
efink prahs ,trohs eht raen ydaer fooh eno htiw dna
.rehtie sraey dab ro doog rof noitanalpxe na evig reven tnuH eht fo sdrol ehT'"
.yromem ni tsrow eht dna
.dnuora lla sdnalssarg eht morf selppir ni gnisir taeh fo sevaw
'.wonk ot su rof ton ,spahrep ,si tI
,ecaep ni rehtegot evil dluoc serutaerc taht seirots eht draeh dah ehS
,erutuF yrruF eht dna
,ylkciuq deifiralc tac eht
spahrep ,ecnatsid eht ni retaw fo tnih a ,ssarg yrD
.elod eht ta nirg eht dehsalf notsirhC ',erus m'I'"
.ailaT ,ykcul era uoY'"
delttes thgiliwt erofeb dnuorg fo ytnelp derevoc
yb remmus toh eht morf devas eb nac ew taht eveileb sredle ruO'"
.cinut thgil sih gnitsujda
,kcab mils reh ssorca gnils sti ni nedrub reh gnitfihs ,dehgis ehS
,ti teg ot ssarg wehc ot evah ll'uoy dna
.deriuqni tacbob eht '?uoy t'nod yhW'"
ssarg eht otni depael ailaT ,taht htiW
,dewollof dah taht gnireffus eht dna
,sniar eht tuohtiW
,reed a ton saw ohw enoemos htiw gnillevart ddo saw tI
,pu dekool notsirhC
.sretae-taem htiw sgnilaed elttil gnivah ot timda I'"
.neddih hteet prahs peek ot depahs saw dezilaer ailaT taht nirg dedispol a
.swalc prahs htiw
ylluferac seilppus sih depparw notsirhC'"
ylthgils denrut eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
'.gnihsif s'gnirps tsal morf kcots ruo fo tsal eht hsif emos dna'"
'.nesohc reh no ezag hsrah a hcus tsac dluow ehs yhw denialpxe evah enoN
doof reh denepo ehS
.deredduhs dna tnecs eht thguac ehs ',llew--deird s'tI
.hcnurc ,hcnurc ,hcnurC
',esoppus I ,srednalssarg eht fo erom ees eW'"
,hself-liat gnikcom a dna
'.egalliv eht pleh dna
.ssarg eht ni hcamots sih no lwarps ot revo dellor notsirhC sa ,delggig ehs
.sklats nekorb eht dima elbisiv won tub ssarg eht ni neddih ylsuoiverp kcor a ta gnilwocs
.tnap ot kcab sih no despalloc dah ohw
,oga sraey owt hguorht emac enO
'.dlrow eht fo erom ees ot ekil d'I'"
.ylteiuq dehgis ehs
.ssarg fo lufhtuom rehtona koot dna
redrob nrehtuos eht gnikram egnar niatnuom eht fo sepols eht pu dna
.ysion emoS .decamirg ehs
.tnangidni saw ylper sih ',esruoc fO'"
,nus remmus eht fo taeh eht rednu
.yrruFoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,erofeb eman eht draeh dah ailaT
".spahrep ,su gniwollof stirips tnuH ruoy hgiH
.eno naht retteb setuor efas dna retaw tuo kcip nac rehtegot owT'" .deddon ehS
,sthguoht rieht htiw enola
,nekorb senoB .senob ekil
,xofyerG ynoT yb
.srehto dna enizagaM taeH
,ruf reh otni gnilttes
,lla retfA .ylsuoituac
.nialp eht ssorca delruc ezeerb a sa
'.evitatneserper ruo sa nesohc saw I
sraey ynam ni remmus gnol tsrif eht saw siht
"?ylurt ,yeht erew tnereffid woH
,emit eht fo hcum gniriter dna teiuQ
,tsevrah on eb dluow ereht
',emoh kcab htolc nwo ruo ekam
egalliv eht neewteb smaerts ehT
serutaerc gnuoy owt eht
etipser yratnemom dedivorp duolc fo psiw a sa desuap reed ehT
.noitseuq eht ta denworf ailaT
ssarg yrd fo hcnurc eht tuo denword rethgual riehT
,srats eht ta derats ailaT'"
.era yeht spahreP'"
.stnemom gnol rof ,yltnelis
.ylefas erom levart nac owt
,sevooh reh rednu gnihcnurc ssarg yrd naht erom gnihton saw ti wenk ehs yllautcelletnI
,tnemom a rof teef sih ni thguac tleb sih morf gnilgnad drows trohs A
dluoc ohw ydobemos ro gnihtemoS
.etsat eht rovas ot ylwols gniwehc
.tcaf ni ,tnuoma gnisirprus A
,tlob ot ydaer llits
'.yad eno seitic eht ot og ot ekil dluow I'"
'?tcaP eht wollof uoy oD'"
.xofyerG ynoT yb
.yliraw daerb eht deye eh ',on tub
fo enilerohs a tsniaga pu gnippal yllautneve
sruoh wef eht ni resolc yltnacifingis nworg dah hcihw
.tsiaw rednu detleb
.no saw esahc eht dna
.dlot neeb dah ehs ,tserof tneb-
.gnihsiruon yrev s'ti tub ,ruovalf elttil sah tI
etag eht tuo reh deklaw dah redle ehT
'.I naht regnuoy hcum lla era htuoy rehto ruo dna snisuoc yM
.werg kcap reh fo thgiew eht
.ailaT ,oot ,ereh kcap eht stcepser enoyrevE'"
,xofyerG ynoT yb mrotS eht emoC
su erofeb enog evah taht esoht ,sdrol eht taht su llet yeht yadoT'"
.yrd ylekil erew tneb-kao dna
,raguoc a saw rotisiv ruo ,woN'" .dias notsirhC
,tnemom a desuap notsirhC
,nur eht otni flesreh werht ehS
.ffilctrohS fo notsirhC ,emoc nehT'"
.peehs dna sgip sedart dna sezar ffilctrohS
.yb gnissap dnuorg eht fo leef eht
wolloh eht otni kcab ylluferac deppets
.ecioVehT ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.tsael ta nurtuo ton dluoc ehs taht ,meht netaerht gnihtyna dluohs laicifeneb eb dluow swalc siH
,gnihtolc nwo reh ta nwod dekool ailaT
.hcnurc ,hcnurc ,hcnurC
notsirhC '.llew sa dnebtuo ot gniog m'I'" ...tsuj ,on ,hO'"
.tsum I tahw od I ,lleW'"
.ti ot depparts-tsehc htiw xo na edor dna
'?kniht uoy od tahW'"
,seunitnoc rehtegot yenruoj s'netsirK dna ailaT woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
'.tfig taht detaicerppa ecnirP eht erus m'I'" .delggig ailaT
.dnegel emas eht evah sredle ruO'"
.hcnurc dna hsiws eht dima drawrof reh evord taht tort kciuq a ni
'?snwod-neerg ni uoy speek tahW'"
yawa raf sa demees llits tserof taht dna
.niaga ecno tserof eht fo neerg eht sdrawot
.ti tsniaga dediced tub
seigolohtna ni derutaef neeb osla sah krow s'ynoT
rewolf nworb ytrid a ekil htrae eht ot detfird dna daerps dna esor taht
flesreh ot delims ailaT
'.yrtnuoc taht fo trap erew ew wenk ylerab eW
.dniw eht ni gnilffur dna
ees eW'" .ylsuoiruc deksa ehs
.snialp eht ssorca decar
,noitnetta reh thguac gnihcnurc rehtonA
.ecnatsid eht ni raf sffulb elbisiv ylerab eht drawot kcab detniop tac gnuoy eht
?daerb-liart emos uoy reffo I naC'"
',neht ,syad eerht spahreP'"
.nwo reh no snialp eht gnissorc naht
dnim s'ailaT ot dednuos tI
trid yrd fo tnecs eht dna ssarg yrd fo hcnurc eht dima
,esruoc fo ,stnerap ym ,lleW'"
,ssarg eht hguorht delffir ezeerb A
,egalliv dezilivic a erew eW'"
.timda ot sekil eh naht regnol rof noitcif yrruf gnitirw neeb sah ohw
'.ecap s'tac a ot pu era yeht fi ksa dluohs reed spahreP'"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs a dnif ro god.ecioVehT
mrotS eht emoC fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s'yadot dnA
'.yawa syad llits si fo erawa m'I retaw gninnur ylno ehT
neeb dah taht hsif fo lerrab a mih evag royam eht ,llacer I fI
,deksa dah ehs ,ereht teg I nehw dnA
,edisa denrut ehs dna ,dekrep srae reH
,enilef eht ot resolc degde ehS .snwoD neerG fo
,retaw hcum ton s'tI'"