,kcab s’rehto eht ssorca depard liat s’enO
.elbatrofmoc sa tsuj si uoy gnivoL
etisbew reh no gnitirw reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
…lla ta gnihton fo lluf sdnim rieht dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.koTkiT dna margatsnI no
,”elbatrofmoC“   yojne esaelP
serutnevda reh fo kcart peek dna
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
”.hcuM gnikcirF oS gnihT sihT evoL I“
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
ohw relletyrots gnolefil a ,ztaK eihpoS yb
,staert fo lluf seilleb riehT
,relevart wollef ruoy floWcaM boR si sihT
,roolf eht no tops ynnus a ni gnizoD
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,tsacdop eht fo tsoh eht osla s’ehS
stac fo riap a s’ereht ,erehwemoS
,ztaK eihpoS yb ”elbatrofmoC“ saw sihT
,sdaeh rieht htaenrednu teknalb yffulf A
.spihs esiurc dna ,stroser ,skrap yensiD rof swohs setirw yltnerruc
.meht yvne t’nod I tuB
ztaK eihpoS yb meop a