,tihs a evag taht ylimaf yna ro ,lla dna esproc a gnivah toN
.esproc gniklaw reh otni dedecer gnol
.yats su sekam taht ereh tes dah seilimaf ruo stoor eht sa
.eid yeht yad eht llit
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
,efil ot kcab daed eht gnirb nac uoY
,floWisakiM yb ”kcaB gnimoC“
;dab taht lla ton s'tI
,knits tsum I hcum woh enigami ylno dluoc I
efil a fo epoh s’ereht
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daeR
taht etaf eht ot flesym dengiser suht I
.efil ot kcab em thguorb naM cigaM ecivon a nehw saw I yrgna
",ereh ylenol yllaer sleef tI"
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
htiw dezilaer I dna
.ecnetsixe tuo-dehcterts a yb degnolorp gnireffus a ,niap
;neewteb ni erehwemos tub ,evila ron
,tnatsni taht ni dna
.nrow dna delios sevlesmeht erew hcihw ,swap reh ni ecaf reh dleh ehS
saw ruf keels demoorg-yletalucammi yllamron reh ,kcor a no detaeS
.em depmud nooccar eht airaM-ysseJ nehw morf kaerbtraeh fo niap eht leef regnol on dluow I deveileR
.eye cilbup eht fo tuo deyats I sa gnol sa dnuora rednaw ot eerf saw I os
.ssenilnaelc fo ecnahc yna pu evag hcum ytterp I ,smoortser cilbup ni snwod-epiw morf edisa os
.em dlot seye reh tahw gnimrifnoc rehtruf
,efil sa emas eht fo erom gniod ylerem tneps erew ytinrete fi
?uoy detiawa taht yrolg gnitsalreve fo dnal A ?nevaeH ni ti sI
”kcaB gnimoC“   :yojne esaelP
.toob ot etoyoc a
.krow ot decrof gnieb morf
?yzzaT ,ti eganam uoy dluoc revewoH"
.os niamer tsuj sgniht emos tub
.sdinac eht morf yawa
,doots ylfeirb liat ym emit tsrif eht saw tahT
.secalp ni ruf reh deretsalp gnivah pmaws eht htiw ,revo lla dettam
.strap eseht dnuora nesiR eerf ylno eht saw I
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.stnuah dlo ym detisiv I ,od ot esle elttil gnivaH .ylwols tiebla
t’nsaw ylbaborp tI
deid yllanif dna
;laeh llits dluoc eW
htaed ni neve spahrep tub
;klofsnwot eht ot gniklat deredisnoc ev’I ,ecnO
.eno siht morf edisa dlrow rehtona ni eb ot hsiw yM
.rehtien s'ti taht tcaf a rof uoy llet nac I
si yrots s’thginoT dna
devil dah ew secalp eht fo ytirailimaf eht evol daed eht neve dna
efil ym denifed dah taht sdnob ylhtrae eht morf eerF .eerf tlef I
saw sihT  .htob su rof
,lausu sa ssenisub saw ti ekil detca I sa gnol sA .ecnetsixe lufgninaem a fo ecnalbmes emos em evag
detnaw ysseJ spahrep taht
?uoy fo tuo snis dna doolb ,ruf eht gnikooc enotsmirb dna erif htiw
,ereh deid gnivah dna gnivil elpoep ynam os htiw taht
,llir a ni dedne eciov reH
,tlas em sa hcus nesiR eht fo eno gnideef
,em derohcna tI .ni
.snezitic gnidnatspu os-ton ylbissop fo
cificeps yrev a tuoba saw
.uoy rof htaeD s’taht ,esac ym ni rO
.dedaf buns reh ta feirg tsap ym lla
,yrotagrup fo ytinrete na ,lleH ti si rO
.lla retfa em htiw detinuer eb ot
,gniees llits tub daed-flah
,srenetsil ,uoy dnimer dluow goD fo tsohG ehT
.mih fo tuo efil nwo sih gnignirw em dah taht
daed rehtien saw I
.deklaw dnik ym fo rehtonA
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
,dewohs edis reh ta hsag dehctits-yledurc A
flesym dnuof suht I dna
,eromyna em ot rettam t'ndid gniviL
,dnuos eht fo ecruos eht ot pu tperc I
.evila gnieb enola tel ,htlaeh doog fo ngis a yltcaxe t’nsi niks hsiyerg yb rehtegot dleh tlep ylggarcs A
.gnivilnu fo etats a ni
,htaed dna efil ym ni emit tsrif eht rof dna ,dias I
,god.ecioveht ta
.)6102(
.seitic eht ni esactun a sa eno lebal ro
.reh was I neht saw ti dnA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sesor fo deb a t'nia
,detsixe I sa gnol sa
.derettam ti doog eht lla rof ,ni llew did I gniht ylno eht tuoba saw tI
?elbissop eb thgim esle tahw
?ecno ta em hguorht ees t’ndluow yeht taht evah I od eetnaraug tahw tub
.gnibbos duol a draeh I nehw
,deid yllanif I nehw oS
eht llifluf ot ecnahc eht d’eh ecno ecaep ni eid oT
gnivah stcud raet
.sllihc eht leef dluoc daed eht neve ylenol os dnuos A
naebbirac eht fo snoitalupop devalsne eht gnoma esora ti nehw eibmoz eht fo htym eht taht
,nosaer emos rof ,esrow sgniht ekam ot demees ylno retaW
lliwdoog dna htiaf no yler yltcaxe t’ndluoc I tnaem emirc a yb daed edam eb ot desoppus saw I tcaf eht tub
.hcuot fo esnes yM .etsat fo esnes yM
woh uoy llet I nehw em eveileb oS
.emosenol laer tog nwo ym no ti gnihguor fo raey a timda ot evah I
,rokoB eht tuB .elbaknihtnu
epoh fo gnirps a
.egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no
lla reffus ot kcab saw I
.klawedis eht otni detlem efil ym sa thgir
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a
.syad eseht seitic eht ot devom elpoep erom dna erom tub
,saw I ereh os dnA
,efil morf tnereffid on eb dluow htaed taht :raef
,floWisakiM yb ”kcaB gnimoC“
,yllaer ,gnisirprus s’tI .enas deniamer I
.ecno naht erom taht yrt t’ndid I os ,ecneinevnocni elbirret a erew smra dna sgel nekorB
gnivom fo ecneinevnocni eht hcum sa s'ti yas emos dna
.noitalsnart ni tsol eb nac
deredisnoc gnihtemos
,snoitidnoc niatrec rednu daed eht morf esir ot hguone sseltser detraped eht ekam dluoc ssenisub dehsinifnu taht dias saw tI .etelpmoc tlef I
,aedi eht enimaxe ot tnaem elat a tneserp ew os dnA
.kool resolc a ekat t'ndid I fi flesym evigrof reven dluow I dezilaer I taht
,daednu eb ot lagelli
.dlrow siht ni devirra I ecnis reve
.setoyoc rehto ynam os delavir dah taht llems fo esnes a fo ssol ehT
,enim ekil tsuj erew seye reH
,devil I nehw talf nial syawla dah liat dna srae yM
.ecnelis s'thgin eht ssorca gniohce
.eciwt eid t'nac uoy tub
ton dna ,siht lla hguorht og uoy od woH
,ssaP s'nerraB fo egde eht ta kooltuo etirovaf ym ta gnittis
feileb sih sa egar ym hcum sa saw ti dna
dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
.taht ekil evitavresnoc erew klof uoyaB
,nezitic a llits lacinhcet saw I sa
,dnuora rokoB erom yna t’nerew ereht ekil ton s’tI
.llih eht fo egde eht ta ecipicerp a
lufrednow siht ni saw I
,railimaf os demees gniluawretac dna sbos eht tuB
morf tnereffid on setsat ti dna tsaot dna sgge tae nac I taht si ecnereffid ylno ehT
.nus eht ni retsef ot tfel feeb dlo-syad
ni eveileb ot yltcaxe tahw swonk reven enO
floWisakiM yb
tnatsnoc fo eno saw efil yM
.enola ti og dluow I
,emit yb detulid eb nac esle gnihtyna ekil raeF
,ecaep devresed-llew s'eno fo tuo deppir gnieb ta yruf dna kcohs eht dnatsrednu reve dluoc gnivil eht fo rebmem oN
,ylimaf eht fo tuo em gnikcik aP morf noitcejer fo gnits eht tlef regnol on I lufknahT
.efil gnikaw dna gnivil ym deugalp dah taht sterger dna hsiugna ,sthguoht eht rebmemer ot elba
,traeh reh revo tnew wap reh sa ysseJ denihw
,esaeler on erew htaed fi
.gnihton on ,seirrow on
",uoy rof emit siht lla gnitiaw yB"
,gnirulla os
,skcits eht ni emocni lufitip a nrae rehtie yam taht enilpicsid a gniyduts sraey dneps ot detnaw ynam toN
.mlac dna thgir os tlef tsuj gnihtyrevE
,"ecnaraeppasid" ym tuoba edam troper yna t'nsaw ereht
.reh derebmemer I woh ekil gnihton dekool airaM-ysseJ
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,lufetarg eb dluohs I taht
.reffo ot dah dlrow eht tihs dna selbuort eht lla morf eerf yllanif saw I
.efiL s’taht ,yas yeht sA
.rehtie doog taht lla t'nsaw ti tub
.sraet on erew erehT
"?gnieb ot kcab thguorb reven erew uoy hsiw
,og ot esle erehwyna dah I ekil t'nsaw tI
koobnoC atseiF yrruF saxeT eht ni deraeppa ylremrof sah ”kcaB gnimoC“
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.lla dna daed-flah gnieb
.gnivilnu fo etats ruo morf su evas dluow
.deirt ev'I ,em eveileB
.gnola lla nalp nwo sih saw taht ,yaw kcis emos ni ,spahrep rO
,detogib dna tnarelotni eb yam seilimaf ruO
taht dias si ti ,woN
,sthguoht on ;ssilb fo etats
,enohPI dlo raey-ruof ym dna srallod wef a rof klawedis eht otni daeh ym devac redynS hpesoJ nehW
,gnivilnu eht fo ew ,feileb ot yrartnoC
,thguorw yeht lleps eht odnu dluoc ohw seno ylno eht erew .neM cigaM eht
.ecaf reh tfel swap reh sa delknirw dna desaerc ksam reH
.tae ot deen llits ,nesiR eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT no
,dinac a rof elbatcepsersid
.meht rof evals sseldnim a deniamer evah dluow I dna regnorts enoyna ,ecivon a tub saw rokoB taht ykcul saw I .niaga revo
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
syawla ,swodahs eht ot tpek I ,doof rof nwot otni og ot dedeen I nehW
].NGISLLAC htiw ,EMAN[ yb uoy rof daer
.eurt erew taht fi tuo gnidnif ni neek t'nsaw I ,saw ti sa citehtap ,efil fo ecnalbmes emos gnivah deyojne I taht neviG
.seiceps ym fo edistuo detad I esuaceb lla
uoyaB eht fo dnal eht ni efiL
eno evas ton dluoc dna