.ni thgir sserp dna ,redrah mih nip tsuj dluow yeht
,sknalf s’retto elttil eht dleh
?meht was enoemos fi tahW
,terref a dna taots a ,sretiaw dah yeht
…d’I fi gnirednow er’uoy tbuod oN
.tnaw ey lla esigolopa nac uoY“
,eugnot sih htiw peed gud retto ehT
sehtolc sih dekcehc rerafaes ehT
,sreksihw sih htiw gnisaet dna gnilkcit
.snioc dlog ,yvaeh ,egral owt htiw
.kniht thgim uoy sa netfo sa ylraen ymodos ni egludni ton od nem ym ,draeh evah thgim uoy sruomur niatrec etipseD
,derad eh sa ylregnig sa
,raeb ot htgnerts sih gnirb neht
.niaga dehctiwt neht
.swap s’retto elttil eht no hsrah saw paos eht dna toh saw retaw ehT .krow ot tes dna
,cnys ni derewop sehcnuah dna htaerb
.yaw taht denoitidnoc er’ew emahs a s’tI
.nisuoc sih ot dewob eh elihw ti gnihsiruolf
hguone ylmrif tsuj ecalp ni mih gnidloh
?ereh ,tahW  .ezorf diS
,naelc ti deffub dna ti deird ,ti desnir ,etalp a dehsaw dah eh emit eht yb tuB
,setunim looc yldesselb wef a mih evag osla sihT
.revo nioc eno denrut eH
.saes eht fo tsaeb a htiw ereht mih part ot
.rehtegot elgnaj t’ndid yeht os
.rettug eht otni nwod delkcirt ti erehw morf
,trap txen eht leef dluow eh wenk eH
?I t’nera ,lamina suoipoc a ma I“
,ebul-rof-loord eht htiw neve
,slamina lla era eW
.hcoorb deruoloc-dlog a htiw
”?niaga ssertsiM noy htiw elbuorT“
,detnurg retto gib ehT
,trop siht ni rohcna deppord ohw sgod-aes ynam naht regnuoy dekool eh hguoht dnA .seye nworb peed
.ecnahc on doots retto-revir llams a
,nrevat eht ot kcab delddaw dna
.emit lanif eno drows sih dna
.tfa sih morf gnilkcirt muc enirtul htiw ,desu ,eros :llaw eht no flesmih deidaets diS
.gnihtyreve was retto elttil deye-neek eht tub ,gnidaf saw thgil ehT .nepo elzzum
lleb eht fo dnuos eht ,srekrow tsom roF
”…eugnot ruoy tcepxe t’ndid I … mu …tsuj s’ti ,yrroS“
,noitalucaje eht rof enO
eno siht piks esaelp
.doog leef ti did ssendoog dnA
.erusaelp sih deyarteb taht
,ecnedac kciuq a tes retto-aes eht erofeb ,ytraeh dna tfos
rettuts mih gnikam
taerg tub ,dnalni rehtruf sdnop dna smaerts eht morf sretto elbaecaep toN
,ereht doots eh daetsni oS
,ssel on regnarts a ,nam rehtonA
.nees reve dah diS taht kcoc-retto tsekciht eht tuo deppils dna
,mriuqs ot ton deirt diS
,roolf eht ffo krof a
.sruobal s’yad eht ot dne emoclew a saw
ytsah a htiw slamina wef a otni depmub eH
,diS retsaM gnuoy
.tfihs rehtona fo dne eht gnillangis
,yawa kool ot dedneterp diS
tsurht dipar hcae
:lamina gib eht ta dellevram diS
.saes eht lias ro dnal no klaw reve ot nem tseimirg eht fo emos htiw ,but a draob-no ,htnom a no-hgin tneps evah I“
.nwot ruobrah eht otni ria-tlas eht gniyrrac dna spihs deroom eht fo slias eht gnirrits ,aes eht morf ni detfird ezeerb gnineve ylrae ehT  kcobnegeiZ yb ”ecneulfnoC“   yojne esaelP
,artxe elttil a yap nac eno erehw sesuoh-erohw fo rebmun doog a era ereht nehw toN
.dnuorg eht no yvaeh gniyal liat-reddur kciht sih
,mih detadnuni stsurht lufrewop fo ovlas a erofeb mih hguorht revihs tnasaelp a gnidnes
,tisiv txen ym nO .em llet tuB
swap gnorts ylsuordnow esoht
,efil otni detrups kcoc taht retal tnemom A
.reyolpme sih morf decaf eh htarw eht retaerg eht ,saw eh taht retal etunim yreve tuB
”.ti hcuoT .daeha og oS“
,noitaicerppa fo rrum peed
.fehc a sa krow t’ndid diS
,yvaeh erew stoob siH .ni desolc dna
.ecnatsid a ta neve ,ksum elam s’retto eht llems dluoc eh erows diS
tsaeb eht esaelpsid ot gnihtyna od ot tnaw t’ndid diS dna
,stekcop etarapes otni snioc eht dehsats eH
,ecnedurP srM saw ereht ,on tuB
,mih no delbmert diS
.yawriats dna petsrood yreve no steksab gnignah dna srewolf htiw
.seenk sih ot deppord dna
,tsiser ot deirt diS
”.fehC ,uoy knaht ,seY“
wam yreksihw sih fo renroc eht
noitasnes lacisyhp laer yrev eht htiw denibmoc egami latnem eht dna
.taht ta tsaeb tcere yldediced a dnA
strad eht dna sdrac eht dna
.nepo diS esae ot stsurht eltneg
,neht llew yreV
,syawyella enotselbboc worran hguorht ruobrah eht morf yawa
,esolc mih gnidloh
.derettam erusaelp s’lamina eno ylno neht thgir
.evael yllautca tpecxe gnihtynA
.desucxe eb ot llenfuT deksa eh
.noitanimoned siht htiw railimaf t’nera uoy tcepsus I
skeehc sih ni gnisir htmraw eht gnileef
.syaw ruoy egnahc yllautca t'nod uoy fi gnihtyna naem t'noD
:doof evres mih tel t’ndid sregdab ehT
,htuoy sih etipseD
yawyella eht morf edorts eh erofeb
,werdhtiw eh sa drah llits saw lamina ehT
hguoht deciton retto-aes ehT
,ehca ot nageb elohliat siH
.hguone ydaets detrats gnineve ehT
.ti dekilsid yeht yas t’ndid yeht ,tsael ta rO
,tfos ,wol a ,delworg retto gib ehT
.erusaelp ni elbmert nisuoc rellams sih edam
.liat elttil s’diS rednu tsam-niam sih knus retto-aes gib eht
.oot esuoh-fo-tnorf dedaeh eh semitemoS
.naom eht elfits ot
.erohw a ro feiht a rehtie sa dekram eb dluow eh
,nwod sehsid ytrid eht tes dna
.dekrims retto-aes ehT .aH
,evom desitcarp a
.evom t’ndluoc diS
,stsurht esoht tuoba sseldnim gnihton saw erehT
.dnabtsiaw sih edisni kcab wap sih deppils retto-aes eht nehw redrah edam saw hcihw
,sdnoces nihtiw htaerb sih thguac ,elihwnaem ,retto-aes ehT
,elkcat kciht ylsuoirolg sih tuo dellup lamina eht
.tfirda tsol saw diS
”.siht ekil ytinutroppo na pu ssap ot gniog ton ma I dnA“
.ycnerruc rellams otni snioc eseht trevnoc ot regnahc-yenom a dnif ot evah dluow diS
,saw eh ereht dna
.yrf llams ,trats enif A“
,mih nip ot desu yeht ,selssut rieht fo eno retfa dna
.reggib erew sretto-aes taht wenk eh dna
,sserd sih detsujda
.moor kcab eht ni mih rof gnitiaw
.ho-yllib ekil truh llits ti tub ,gnipleh erew mucerp suoreneg dna avilaS
.htaerb denetrohs htiw tiebla
,kaeps ot elbanu llits ,teY
,erats taht ta rednuolf ot tfel erew staorhttuc dna mastolf denedrah-elttab fI
.ecnalg tsrif ta euqserutcip oS
.seidob nwo ruo tuoba hsidurp os t’nerew ew hsiw od I“
,ylerab tub ,noitartenep eht desae mucerP
,raer dehtolc s’diS revo gnidnirg ,lufgninaem
.thgin remmus hserf siht no
.noos oot lla emac ti
,dehctiwt yeht dna
,raeg txen eht ot pu deppets retto-aes eht nehw dnA
.dnim t’nod uoy fi ,ysatnaf ’yob yoc‘ eht fo ssel elttil a dnA“
,wap sih ,ydob sih
,rehtaef s’torrap a ekil dekool tahw htiw detaroced
.gnikool uoy was I sulP
,ssenelam sih fo htgnel eht gninnur sniev kciht htiw ,ytfeh saw lamina ehT
?was ohw erac eh t’ndid rO
,aera laitnediser a si sihT
,setarc dna sloot dna sepor htiw gnikrow erew stsaeb
,hctorc sih fo tnorf ni swap sih dessorc diS
.retto-aes a saw sihT
,ssenelam sih dezeeuqs dna desaet eH
,dedecer retaw eht fo wolf ehT
.edis sih yb pmil swap sih
,ecnats ediw a koot eH
,snap rieht detaeh dna snevo rieht derif maet kooc sih dna llenfuT
,rehtona yb dewollof
.nrut ni eno hcae gninaelc
.maerd a tsuj saw taht ,hguoht won roF
.rehtona ro yaw eno ,emit no pu nrut ot uoy teg lliw I ,uoy llet I
.gninraw a eb siht teL“
.nam wollef rieht htiw denummoc yeht erofeb dereviled staorht-tuc dednah-ynroh ynam tbuod on sa
.lliw uoy tahT“ ”.evaheb ll’I …I“
taht maerd a deruobrah llits diS
.swap sih yb thgir dewolf won ksum retto eht erehw
”.wollef lufecruoser a ekil mees uoY
.erusaelp htiw denoorc diS dna
tsaeb dalc-nikserof eht fo sehcni dlotnu htiw
,ni tes gnineve eht dna tes nus eht sA .sseltops saw ti
…ydob taht dekrow eh yaw eht rof sA
.noitnetta gnidnamed ,gnibborht ,emosraef saw lasuora sih tey
.mih ekat ot delggurts yeht
s’retto eht fo ytisnetni eht nevig
.mih erofeb lamina eht fo tfeh eht dna
.ffo gnisae kcoc god-aes fo sehctiwt eht
,llaw eht ecaf ot
,noisseforp eht ni nevE
.lla ta evom t’ndid eh ,dne eht nI
,eh naht regnorts erew maerts s’diS no syob tsoM
.flesmih gnihtolc-er erofeb ,yaw eht lla mih
.daehkcoc daorb sih gnirevoc nikserof dedlof fo tnuoma suoiciled a dna
”.ecnahc on evah dluow uoy ekil yppug elttil A
,smra sih dessorc retto-aes ehT
.elzzum trohs s’diS dnuora desolc bmuht a dna regnif A
,yawyna kaerb sih rof emit ylraen saw tI
.edart a ylp ot evah slamina lla ,tuB
:mrif saw god-aes eht tuoba gnihtyrevE .mih rof ereht
.ti fo leef eht deyojne neve diS dna
,tsrif ta wap eno htiW
.thgiarts klaw llits dna gorg fo sdraknat nezod a flah yawa tup dluoc eh ekil dekool eh
.slesihc dewolley niwt ekil hteet htiw staR
,dellits mrots eht
.eciov s’retto-aes eht ni esirprus on saw erehT
retto-aeS ”.étnahcnE .nayleverT“ ”.diS …mU“
.etal pu gninrut no peek uoy fi fehc suos a uoy ekam reven ll’yeht tuB
.yawyella eht ni mih denioj lamina rehtona nehw
.llew sa uoy hsinup annog t’nia I ,lleW“
”.ees I tahw ekil I ,eno elttil ,yakO
,gniyarps saw retto eht drah woh yb gnigduj dnA !weiv lluf ni
,ecap peek ot diS rof hguone tsuj
sesuoh rieht ot gnidnet ro sdoog gniyrrac slamina gnoma evow eH
,nerdlihc s’eno gniees fo esimorp eht saw ereht
.etulas yvaN lacuD a fo noitamixorppa tseb sih htiw dednopser
.etal er’uoy taht etunim yreve rof gnihtraf eno uoy gnikcod m’I ,no won morF
.derepmihw diS dna
.nruter sih no etsaw nehctik eht otni ti pils dluoc eH .deddon diS
hcihw ,slobmys erew ereht edis eno enO
,tegrat sih dnuof retto-aes ehT
,sepols eht otni deltsen
,drawrof dehsup eh dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.uoy ekil pmirhs elttil a ta eciwt kool t’ndluow klof tsoM
.eurt deyats gnitsurht sih dna ,thgit
.ydob ym gniwohs tuoba smlauq on evah I ,trap ym rof dnA  .seY“
,tleb sih ta retsloh a dna drows a
.tsetnoC yrotS trohS yrrufoS 1202 eht fo renniw dna ,)emit emas eht ta ylerar hguoht(
,fehc daeh dna elom ,llenfuT
,knar fo tsaeb a eh saW
.eno elttil ,uoy tuoba snoicipsus ym evah did I
,yltnedifnoc ,ylhtooms ,ylwolS
.mlac fo sisao na saw edistuo
,rehtona eno htiw cnys ni gniwolf
:dluoc eh tahw derehtag eH
,dekcap saw nrevat ehT
?reggib hcum siht tuB
.eltsuh dna stuohs htiw dellif saw edisretaw ysub ehT
,erats sih fo ssentsafdaets eht ni ebyam gnihtemos
,edutilos fo tnemom siht gniyojne
,etatsorp s’diS otni gnivird saw tsurht hcae hguoht dna
,llor ot retto-aes eht rof hguone dedleiy dna delttes dah diS nooS
,dloc nar retawhsid sih ,neht dna woN
.reisae edisni pils hself gnitseuq gniborp drah mrif taht ekam ot gnihtyna
.gnola retto elttil eht gut ot dna
.eugnot taht fo ecalp eht koot elam erom dna remraw raf gnihtemos noos tuB
,flesmih ot ralimis oS
.ssenisub gniretac eht fo ecneirepxe on htiw ,nehctik rieht ni esool keerc retawkcab emos morf retto elttil emos tel ot tuoba t’nerew yeht tuB
retto sseleman gib eht sa
,god-aes eht hguorht delbmur lworg suotnetrop a sa
?uoy t’nera ,pup elttil yrgnuh a era uoy
,gar-hsaw a dna etalp tsrif eht pu dekcip
tsrif sih gnivig ,degilbo diS
.no gniyrruh erofeb ’yrros‘
,evoba morf elkcuhc a saw erehT .ekorts a piks dna
,nrets lufrewop sih evord rolias eht nehw dna
– sevlesmeht tuo doof eht thguorb yeht esle ro
.enigami ylecracs dluoc diS hcihw
:revewoh ,bbe eltneg a ot delttes reven yehT
.dleiy ot detrats elohliat s’diS litnu ,drawrof dna
,slias sih morf ria eht dekconk tsurht hcaE
,raewdaeh on denwo ohw ,diS
.lautum si erusaelp eht ,em eveileB“
,seturb derruf-eltsirb dna ynwarb
.dloheb ot gnihtemos saw
,nwot siht hguorht gnissap sredart dna srolias fo sknar eht dnuora yaw sih dezeeuqs diS dna
,nrut ot retto eht dediug yehT .erus
.senotselbboc eht no pmuht-pmuht dilos a
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
”.ecnedurP srM ,uoy knaht ,seY“
.thgil wol eht ni netsilg pit s’lamina eht gnikam
,tneitap saw god-aes ehT
.tlah a ot noitangissa rieht gnirb dna
,erom mih perp ot god-aes eht deksa evah dluoc
,ffurcs s’diS ot etib emosraef a htiw ekorb hcihw mrots a
tsaf spihs rieht gnikam
,llaw eht no swap debbew ,gniredduhs
,hguoht retto eno roF
mlap debbew s’retto elttil eht dessorc dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,taht htiw dnA ”.gnineve dooG“
.dnoyeb eliriv dna drah
.erusaelp fo tsim a ni sthguoht sih gniduorhs ,psag dna
.suonimo dna mrif taht
,sretto-revir elam rehto nees dah eh ,pu gniworG
,liat s’diS detfil rolias ehT
”.eeregdek ruoy sekil yeht hcum woh rettam oN
,renroc eht dnuora deppils dna
”.deen ni etam a pleh I riaf ylno s’ti esoppus I ,llew yreV
.semit edit eht ro edart fo ekops yeht sa ylnepo sa tnemhsilbatse reh dna reh fo ekops sreog-nrevat dna elpoepsnwot eht
,revewoh ,nrevat eht edisni ot derapmoC
.ti mialc ot neek naht erom ma I dna ,skeew ni dah ev’I liat tsecin eht er’uoY
.ti epiws dna yrt t’nod tsuJ“
,lla dna sllab ,hctac sih elkcat ot wap dnoces sih desu diS .drah ,dehctiwt lasuora elohw eht dna
.gniyrd ylwols saw taht neve hguoht
.tsaeb suoreneg a hcuS
.ograc rieht gnidaolnu dna
,dnoces a gnitatiseh tuohtiw dnA .diS ta thgiartS
.deruoloc-itlum dna gnol
.wap s’retto elttil eht fo gnibbew eht derevoc mucerp yksum ,kcilS
”.dal emosdnah a era uoy
,kcoc sih no wap debbew a fo erawa ylmid saw diS
ela gnilzzug nem eht gnoma
.retto ynroh fo tnecs eht pu revoc tuoba tsuj dluow hsif ehT
.sdrow sih sa htooms sa saw eugnot s’retto ehT
,liob ot detrats ecuas a dnoces eht enevretni ot kciuq saw ohw ,llenfuT fo eye lufhctaw eht rednu lla
.sremotsuc rof nepo saw rood tnorf eht
,gniytpme dedeen nisab sih emit txen ehT
,neht thgirlA“  .deplug diS
.thgin eht rof yppup ym edisgnola tsaper dna sgnigdol emos evah dna
,skeew ni laem dekooc-emoh tsrif rieht otni gnikcut dna
,diS edisni deirub erew kcoc-retto fo sehcni ytaem eerhT
”…semit etairporppa fo gnikaeps dnA“
,pu ezag ot dah diS
,tnorfretaw eht yb noonretfa taht elihw gnol doog a tneps dah eH
.sretto eht erew ereht ,esruoc fo dnA
.syawedis dekool eh dna
,erif a revo retaw fo nisab a tes ,elihwnaem ,diS
.daer ton dluoc eh hcihw tub
esaeler tnecer s’retto-aes eht fo erutxim a
.snehctik dna nrevat eht fo esion eht dna taeh eht morf yawa
,gnorts erew swap s’god-aes gib eht ,paos yb denehguor ylthgils ylno ylthgils swap sih dna ,mils erew smra s’diS erehw tub ,debbew erew slamina htoB .ti pota dnah rellams sih gnitser ,wap eht derimda retto-revir eht dna ,edis eht no wap a htiw ydaets diS dleh eH .sevaw eht htaeneb dna no efil a rof denoh dna nweh ,elcsum htiw dekcap tey ehtil ydob sih ,gnorts saw retto-aes ehT .eb dluohs ti sA
.ni lla ti gnikat ,dehgis diS
,htped tcaxe eht wenk eH
,skeehc gniwolg hguorhT
,tops eht no denrut retto-aes ehT ”.ueida uoy dib I
,sesuoheraw eht dna
,tnuoma tsethgils eht
.emit ruoy rof esnepmocer riaf naht erom siht dnif ll’uoy kniht I
”?os kniht uoy
.regit latneirO gnilrans a htiw devargne saw edis rehto ehT
”.niaga etal ,yob ,era’y ereH“
,llaw eht pu yawflah ksum retto toh gniyarps
.sreklaw-teerts eht rof og syawla t’nod I ,yldettimdA
?noitavrats lanrac fo skeew retfa llif rieht koot srevol rieht sa ,thgin taht erusaelp ni tuo yrc dluow slamina ynam woH
,hcuop nioc sih ot denruter nayleverT
,retal sdnoces suoiruf ,ereM
,nioc a tuo dellup eh ,swalc owt htiW
.lamina siht yned ot tnaw eh did ron
htaerb sih rednu gniremmis lworg a
.thgin eht rof rentrap s’eno htiw gniriter erofeb
?krow uoy od erehw ,yppug ,em llet oS“
,kcobnegeiZ yb ”ecneulfnoC“
.seitud sih demuser rolias ehT
…drawrof flesmih evird ot stonk fo etar tcaxe eht
.erom ro ,net emoceb dluoc sgnihtraf evif ,did eh fI
,gnihtemos dias evah dluoc diS
.sselemahs os ,tnedifnoc oS
.nisuoc rellams sih ot tah sih deppit dna ,diS deciton eH
,diS dnuora mra lufrewop a depparw eh dna
,mih tuoba gnipeews kaolc sih
.yawa dekrow retto eht
.esruoc fo ,semit etairporppa eht tA
,retto elbmuh a ,eh fI
,yalp tsuj saw ti tsrif tA
.ria hserf eht yojne ot emit os
,snoolatnap sih otni wap a deppils
”.enola thginot rof tsuj sgnihtraf evif s’taht oS
.neht recnaleerf a oS“
,ecnedurP srM seY“
,mih edistuo ,mih edisni
.elam wollef sih ot regnarts on saw diS
,snioc esoht gniyduts er’uoy yltnetni woh yb gnigduj ,woN“
.daorb ylemosraef dna ,duorp ,llaT
.su yaper uoy woh si siht dnA“
.dnuof eb ot liat si ereht ,ereh neve teY
.ecnedifnoc fo lluf ,kram hserf sih ot txen
.erom rof hcraes ot dah flesmih diS
.detcurtsni sa did dna deplug diS
,lebariM emadaM nees deedni ro tem reven dah diS hguohT .tbuod on saw ereht woN
…sdeen lanosrep sih ot gnidnetta saw
,emit a ta kcub erus trohs
,elbissop sa hcum sa ,xaler ot liat sih gnilliw
.seotpit sih no doots retto-revir eht taht os diS detfil dna
,kcoc sih pu elkcirt mucerp eht tlef retto gib ehT
.ereht diS dah eH
.detaes ydaerla erew snortap ruof ro eerht ,edisni tnew eh nehw deednI !tsalB
,tsiser ot deirt reve diS fi dnA .elbarenluv tsom saw eh erehw
,tcnitsni no dna ,edisa tes erew sresuorT
,mih gnisserac saw retto siht ,oN
.emosdnah era uoy tuB“ ?noisseforP
.edih ot detnaw eh ,yats ot detnaw eh ,nur ot detnaw eH
.ylsuht em deruonoh enoemos ecnis emit gnol A“
,kcab kaolc sih gnipeews
.gnola dewolf ylpmis dna
,ereh etalp ytrid a
,ti yojne htob ew fi dnA
,selkcub gninihs htiw stoob rehtael erow osla eH
.epols eht nwod raeppasid retaw eht dna sdus eht gnihctaw
.tnereffid saw ,revewoh ,thginoT
.kcorb gib eht ot
,pirg sih denethgit diS .ezis ni tsael ton
.nrub ot nageb niap eht erofeb hcni na ylerab gnidleiy
eno mih otni gnikrow
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,elzzum s’diS desaeler retto-aes ehT
.gniod saw eh tahw wenk eH
segattoc enots neewteb detsiwt hcihw
.ytiniffaruF dna yrrufoS no
.egayov fo selim dnasuoht a fo ekops taht
.nemes retto ni detaoc saw ti ,wap sih ta dekool eh nehw dna
,pu ezag sih detlit diS
,ecalpkrow sih ot yaw tsekciuq eht saw siht wenk diS .lla ta emit oN
?toohs tub gnihtyna od retto lufrewop a hcus dluoc woh
,sselhceeps saw elihwnaem diS
,ydaerla gnihctiwt saw retto gib ehT
”.noos niaga em ees ll’uoy ,yrrow uoy t’nod tuB
ezis eht mohtaf ot tseb sih gniyrt
.tsaeb ywenis dna ehtil a
.ecniw ot ton gniyrt
.elbuod eht no nehctik eht ni ey tnaw I woN
.nwot eht hguorht deirrucs dna ruobrah eht ot liat sih denrut diS !niaga ton ,hO
,rood nehctik eht morf secap wef a saw rettug ehT
.tniop a dah nayleverT
”.srelles sa llew sa sreyub seriuqer gnidart dnA
.yoj htiw dehgual dna
.sllaw renni s’retto-revir eht gnola lla devrac eh woh nevig
”…I …I“ .derettuts diS
.lliw I ,lamina wollef ym ot yporhtnalihp emos wohs nac I fi …oS“
.nirg a otni detfil
”.tleb ruoy tuc ll’I ro
.psarg sih ni dellews ti dna
,drow tsal eht depsag diS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,kcobnegeiZ yb
piy diS edam kcub prahs a litnu sekorts s’rehto hcae gnihctam
.erom mih gnihcterts ,redrah
,lamina eht tlef diS elihwnaeM
,won repeed saw noitcere retto ehT
,llaw ybraen a ot denrut eh
.redral eht fo tuo daeh sih dekop
,ruf foorpretaw fo lufhtuom sih otni delrans tsaeb-aes eht erofeb thgir gnineppah retnuocne eht fo tnemom laref ylno eht
.tuo dellac retto elttil eht woN
,mih dehsinomda evah yam retto-aes eht tub ,naom ot detnaw diS
,selprup dna seulb
.nrub ot detrats tellif a ro
,srood nrevat nepo eht morf deirrac rethgual dna rettahc fo dnuos ehT
,thginot rof sa dnA
,tekcop sih morf feihcrekdnah a dellup retto-aes ehT
.tleb sih ta hcuop nioc a denepo rolias ehT
pop lanif taht litnu pu thgir tnasaelp ylgniredduhs dna ylwols
”.sresuort ruoy pord woN
,drawrof desserp retto gib eht llits dna
,secalp dellevart dah ohw retto na saw sihT
.eugnot enirtul kciht taht yb detartenep
sdnal dna serohs nees dah ohw
.kcab eugra ot ton wenk eh ,llitS
.hguoht meht erimda dna pots ot emit oN
psarg gnorts s’lamina eht ni detneler eh tub
”...suoiruc er’uoy fi ,paos redneval sekil eH
.redro ni kcab flesmih gnittup detrats dna
.spihs eht tuoba lla wenk diS ,esruoc fO
.reggaws eht dah ylniatrec eH ?neve niatpac a
,erats ylno dluoc retto-revir ehT
,rettug eht dna selbboc eht ta derats
.hguoht rab eht dniheb ydoboN
.llew sa sllab-retto gnignah-wol sih gniveirter emit siht
.yks gnineve ylrae eht rednu aes eht fo hsaws eltneg eht ,ecnatsid eht ni dna
.yap ni tuc a droffa ylecracs dluoc eh
.nwot eht rof ekam dluow slamina gnikrow-drah esoht ,nooS
.dettops eb t’ndluow eh ,kciuq saw eh fi ebyaM
,spih s’diS no pirg mrif a koot eH
,hteet gniraet-hsif prahs fo lluf nirg a dehsalf retto-aes ehT
.kool taht wenk eH .derevihs diS
.ssenlooc neddus eht morf deredduhs tsomla diS
dehctaw diS .steerts eht otni dna
.elbixelf erom raf saw tI
.sruobhgien elbatuper emos evah uoY .eno elttil ,hsuH“
.ruobrah elttil siht otni gnillup evol od I ,hO“
”.sdlrow htob fo tseb eht ylurT .nameltneg a ro
”.etal m’I yrros m’I ,wonk I
.hctiwt txen yrev eht no diletsum elttil thgit siht otni llips ot ylno
,htgnel diccalf sih dnuora wap debbew a depparw tsaeb-aes ehT
”.elbuort ruoy rof rehtona dna
.edam ecno eh eeregdek taht yojne ot demees dnabsuh reh dna ecnedurP srM ,eurT
skcod eht ssorca llA
.pu peews ot dah eh hcihw ssalg nekorb a neve
.hseef fo tol a yub lliw taht yas ot eciffus ,lleW“ ”.ton ma I .riS oN“ ”.noitanimoned
,nehctik eht dellif hsif gniyrf hserf fo elzzis eht dna ssih ehT .yad eht fo sredro doof tsrif eht kooc ot nageb dna
?dnilb erew selom taht dias ohW
.liat s’diS fo pit eht ot hctiwt a gnidnes kcub hcae
.edalb sih ot wap eno deppord rerafaes ehT
.ylpeed gnilahxe dna taorht sih gniraelc
,retto eht dehcuot eh ,gnirevaw htaerb sih htiW
…thgin eht fo ydal a dnif ot setunim wef a klaw ylno deen eno
,retaw eht hguorht efink dna ekans ot
.daeh sih koohs ylpmis diS
.yaw eht yb ,tnemyap snaem taht
,sgniliar nori eht no gninael
.ybraen stnemhsilbatse rehto eerht ro owt eht morf dna
,liat-reddur kciht taht fo ecnalab dna esiop eht ,htgnerts sih
,em uoy eveileb dna
.thgil nretnal eht ni dlog gnitnilg meht fo eno tsael ta
daeh sih deppid eh oS
.saes eht no sriasroc dna stsaeb tsecreif eht htiw sdrows ssorc I ,rebmemeR
,weiv fo tuo kcoc gib taht deppils retto-aes eht nehw nevE
.nrevat eht ni thgin ysub a fo mortsleam elohw eht dna
nisab latem eht nwod tes eH
.sehtolc rieht hguorht gnisserp snoitcere drah ,mih no bur
,”hcuot lanosrep eht fo trap llA“
,nrevat eht fo sdnuos eht htiw erom ecno decalper
.daehkcoc s’lamina eht wohs ot kcab ti dils ylluferac diS dna
.ylrae ffo mih tel elom eht os
,ton ro emag eht ot weN
”.emit ruoy fo tnemom a rof erac
,esool saw nikserof taht fo llA
,muc-retto fo egrus a derif eh dna ,detloj ydob sih
.drah ylbidercni dna htooms
.yaw eht ni gnihtolc emoselbuort on dna ,elbaezis eroM
,snehctik eht ot denruter retto ehT
”.ytiutarg artxe elttil a ni worht yam I ,elbaroda siht gnieb no yrrac uoy fi ,swonk ohw dnA
.meht nioj dluoc eh
,tnereffid os tey dnA
.gnihctiwt dna drah reddur elttil nwo sih ,derrum diS
,dekaeuqs eh dna ecnatsiser sih tsap deppils lamina drah eht litnu pu thgir
.thgin yrrats ,raelc ,looc a saw tI
.edart ruoy ecnuonna uoy gniraeh ot yldnik oot ekat t’ndluow yehT
.diS ot ti dednah dna
,retto taht fo ezis eht nevig ,niaga nehT
,ecaps lanosrep s’diS ni peed saw retto-aes ehT
,yad eno ebyam ,yad eno
,sehsid rieht gniraperp ,snoitats rieht neewteb devom slamina eht dna
,htaerb rof gnitnap
,nni eht dehcaer dah retto gnuoy eht emit eht yB
?yella kcab eht nI
,tuo retaw sih deciuls diS
”.noisseforp ruoy ni drowhctaw eht si noitercsid ,rebmemeR
,ecnatsiser sih tsap gnivled erofeb elohliat elttil s’diS fo mir eht dnuora gnippal
sresuort ruoy pord woN
.seye gniyrp morf yawa ti hsats ot erus eb tsuJ
.elohliat sih ta desserp hself kciht teW
”.ecnedive taht laecnoc nac uoy tsurt I woN“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
…tfos dna ,neklis saw tI
.ti dneps uoy woh luferac eb dnA
.delims retto gib ehT ”?ecin …tlef tahT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.yaw eht yb ,mu ,uoy knahT“
,gnirats nisuoc rellams sih deciton nayleverT .kcoc-retto fo hsalf gniteelf lanif a thguac diS .flesmih gnignarraer saw elihwnaem nayleverT
.deen a dah ylniatrec eh
- meht ni deerb elbinrecsid on htiw seninaC
,sgnigdol nwo sih dna doof neewteB
,ezeerb aes eht ot elohliat sih gnisopxe
,esnet werg pirg siH
.retteb eht hcum os neht
.flesmih dniheb dehcaer eh ,tnemirepxe na sA
.ydaer os ,mrif os
.sraey sih dnoyeb raf ecneirepxe dewohs hcihw
,miws ot tliub slamina owt ,detam yehT
,etarebiled erom emaceb gnibbur eht ,noos tuB
,kcil ytsah on saw sihT
evaw a ekil diS hguorht gnihsarc
,redart raluger a ot eseht fo eno dednah
tnorf eht ta denetsaf
,hguor ylreporp dna ,deggur
.daeh sih deddon dna dehgis diS
.ynirb dna peed eht fo sretto-aes
,draeb s’enutpeN“
,emit erom yna etsaw ot tnaw t’ndid eH .did diS
,gnineppah saw tahw wenk slamina htoB .rehtona neht
.syawegassap fo nerraw gnipols gnitsiwt siht gnoma
.tnemyolpme uoy ’nivig ,ruovaf a uoy gniod m’I wonk uoY
,eerf deppils eugnot eht nehW
.swap koohs retto-revir dna
,noitcere enirtul kciht taht yllaicepse dna
”?syob s’lebariM fo eno uoy erA
.lamina gib eht dnuora dluoc eh tseb sa wap sih gnisolc ylwols
,llaw eht tsniaga tnael lamina gib ehT
.ecitsuj meht od t’ndid ’lergnom‘ drow eht
,teiuq tpek eh daetsni tub
.ereh llits er’uoY .oS“
.dezafnu ,deunitnoc retto-aes eht ”,dneirf yM“
,wol gninnur saw yreltuc eht fi ,semitemos tuB
,od ot drah saw taht teY
,nisab eht otni paos-hsid emos detarg diS
,reyolpme sih dna ydaldnal regdab eht
”.uoy knaht ,wonk I“
,draykcod eht ssorca tuo gnar lleb A
”.siht tnaw uoy wonk I
,sdrawpu depols steerts worran ehT
”...noisseforp eht ot wen ylraelc ,trohs ,gnuoY
elzzum sih fo ssenhguor eht
si hcihw ,em ekil retto na dnA
,hself gnitrap fo kcilhcs a htiw dnA .debborht eh dna
”.daeha thgin ysub a su stoG
.ydaer teg uoy stseggus I woN
.krow s’gnineve na ni llA
.kcoc s’retto eht t’nsaw ti tuB
,deye-ediw tnew diS
.flesmih gniduned retto elttil eht ta
.nommoc ni dah yeht gniht ylno eht saw taht ,revewoH
.yas dluow ecnedurP rM
elzzum trohs s’diS dnuora wap a depparw retto gib eht yletaidemmI
,yreksihw saw elims siH
.elims lufhtrim a htiw deretnuoc nisuoc siH
.nisuoc rebbuldnal sih revo toof doog a gnimool
.daeh s’diS evoba llaw eht no wap eno decarb retto-aes ehT
.delims nayleverT
”.thgin ysub a eb annog s’ti os ,yadot trop otni emac spihs gib emoS
.tcatnoc eye niatniam ot ,ylthgils kcab nael neve
…pu taht wollof dluow tahw kniht ot dnA
,erutaretil yrruf citore fo rotaerc a
.wap-dnah s’diS revo gnippird dna kciht
.niev tnenimorp eno gnola pitregnif a gnicart ,ekorts luferac
…a saw eh kniht retto eht diD  .tiaW .hO
,tekcub hsaw sih derehtag eh ,nehT
.detiawa snehctik eht
sepor gniluah fo tluser eht tbuod on
,drow sih ot eurt dnA
…uoY“ .ruf keehc s’diS rednu tliub htmraw ehT
.edistuo tnemugra rieht ekat ot deen did yllaer yeht ,sey taht ro ,emit gnisolc saw yllaer ti ,sey taht tnih rehtruf on gnideen ,ti ta nwod kcab dluow srolias nworG
.edis s’diS otno dleh swaP
.rehto hcae morf delpuocnu sretto eht dna
,srevotfel eht ffo deparcs eH
.tuo dehcaer diS
,emoh nwot siht dellac ohw esoht roF
,mih tuoba nrow-mrots gnihtemos llits saw ereht
.retnuoc eht no pu gnilip erew setalp dna sessalg tsrif eht ,gnol erofeb dna
,won kaerb no saw eh ,lleW
,rednet saw liat-rednu siH
,swap sih detcepsni
,daeh sih pota tah nrocirt a dna
.tekram hsif a ton
.liat sih dna kcoc sih morf ,gnippird saw diS
”?rof ksa I od mohw
,nopaew s’retto eht dehtaehs diS
.dlog fo tnilg eht ees dluoc diS taht hguone tsuj
.reviuq elohliat sih edam kcohsretfa na sa
.tahw rettam on ,etal eb ot gniog saw eh tub
.retto rehtona saw tI
.emit a ta skeew dna syad rof slias gniggir dna
.ydaerla fehc a dah yeht ,sediseB
.tifeneb a syawla
,saes nretsae eht morf egaugnal-lobmys emos eb ot wenk diS
,regnorts semit net ,yltnatsni elzzum sih dehcaer ksum ehT
…noitarenumer ruoy fo rettam llams eht ,woN“
.muc retto ni detarutas saw ti litnu tsael ta
.erom detnaw diS dnA
.deffocs ydal regdab ehT
,tnemom taht ta dnA
.krow fo yad drah a retfa ni xaler ot sesuohtseug dna snni erew ereht
.flesmih ekuD eht gniugnot ekil si liat ruoy gniraperp ,eno elttil ,nosirapmoc yB
.ylesiw ti eldnah ll’uoy erus m’I hguohT
drows dna nep htob sdleiw ohw taog a
,seuh citauqa peed htiw delttom kaolc a ni desserd saw eH
.rettug eht otni retaw gnimaof eht deruop eh erehw ,kcab tuo yawegassap eht ot nisab eht koot eh dna
,nikserof taht fo sdlof eht ni deloop dah taht mucerp eht dna
.niap prahs eht ta gnizeerf
,elkcirt a ot dewols maerts s’retto gib ehT
,nrow-rehtaew ,gnortS
elohliat s’diS revo bats tnulb a
.senob nekcihc dna sparcs doof ni derevoc setalp dna sessalg htiw dedaol swap sih
,erehwesle saw emoh esohw esoht roF
,mraw taht eb dluoc gniht eno ylno taht wenk eh
,daeh sih morf tah derehtaef sih tpews eH
.knas traeh s’retto elttil ehT
.gnola gnillorts ylpmis ro
”.wonk uoy ,flesti lias t’nseod pihs A
.desuora ,tnedifnoc
.stsaeb-aes eht fo sgniog dna sgnimoc eht gnihctaw
.ereh evah ew tahw ees s’tel
?ereht llits saw diS wonk eh diD
…elam wollef ruo etaicerppa htob I dna uoy
.feiler fo tnurg a htiw daeh dna sredluohs sih gnillor
”ecneulfnoC“ saw sihT
.neht thgirlA“ ”.fehC ,wonk I“
rethgual deggur eht gnoma
,kool ot erehw swonk eno ecno dnA
,pit s’lamina eht ta deloop mucerp tew taht fo lla dna
.flesmih pleh t’ndluoc eH
,htrof dna kcab owt ro hcni na