”?semit dlo ekil foor eht no tuo gnah nac eW
redlof ycaripsnoC eht rednu noitagitsevni reh fo syad wef eht gniliated
.stcejorp gnitirw erutuf rof
.deyalprevo erew yeht tlef tsuJ“
,noinuer loohcs hgih a gnirudne ereh derevocsid
.foor eht fo trap delgna na no nwod gnittis erofeb htmraw rof rehtegot swap dnah reh sbur repraH
!flesym naht rehto eno on rof krow I“
.lworg ot egru eht gnitsiser ,sehctiwt elzzum s’ymereJ fo edis thgir ehT
,lotsip eht gnitniop elihw resolc sklaw repraH nehW
.enilno hcum detsop yllaer reven eH
?yllaer ,uoy era ohw ,oS
sih s’ti sa gnieeS
elitsoh ylnepo erew ohw esoht gnihctapsid reisae ti sdnif netfo ymereJ
,yltcerid mih pleh ot ecneulfni fo erehps s’eeL repraH esu ton dluoc eh fi neve dnA
.uoy gnillet reven rof yrros m’I“
.sthgieh fo diarfa neeb syawla s’eh ,dnoceS
,yrtnuoc eht ssorca nwot yreve ni ,mih ekil ynam neeb evah erehT
sdneirf ro ylimaf yna denoitnem reveN
.sdneirf rehto reh htiw esrevnoc ot yawa skaerb repraH
.tsap sraey fo stohs dworc ni mih erew meht fo tsoM
,hgis lufworros tfos a sevig repraH
yojne esaelP  .nesraL ymereJ
,regnol setunim wef a rof stiaw ymereJ
,boj reporp a gnitteg ton rof yaw emos ni deliaf yeht ekiL
,snoitagilbo sih rof t’nsaw ti fI
.eerged siht ot secnereferp s’enoemos fo erawa repyh eb dluow
.anatnoM ni erehwemos yawa flesmih gnikcut dna
enohptrams eht no mih fo snoitagitsevni s’repraH fo secart lla burcs ot si ssenisub fo redro tsrif s'ymereJ
,shtaerb peed wef a gnikat dna gnilffinS
.kcab shtnom owt tuoba ecnamrofrep elitsnruT a thguaC“ ,selims ymereJ
.redluohs thgir sih spat dnah tfos llams a
,eb ot tuo edam ylsuoiverp sa renol a fo hcum t’nsaw ymereJ dlo eht ,yltnerappA
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.emit eht ssap ot snaem a dnif ot sdeen ylpmis eh dna
,dlrow xelpmoc reve siht evivrus ot erew eh fI
”?thgirla gnihtyreve ,yeH“ ,pu skrep eH
,ward eht htiw rekciuq gnieB
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”?gniod I saw tahW“
,dnuora snrut ylwols ymereJ  ”!srewsna tnaw I
,sdnopser ymereJ
su fo htob rof tseb s’tahw od woN !hguonE“
,skcarc eht hguorht llaf ot si ti tahw swonk ohw nam a
”.dekil eh tahw ot kcuts syawlA
sselwalf si yrots siH
.yxalag yaW ykliM eht fo tsom tuo ekam ot elba erew owt eht
.wenk I ymereJ eht morf tnereffid era uoY
,seunitnoc repraH
.klaw ekac a eb dluohs
?enoyna llet t’ndid eh fi
.em rof tuo dekool dna
!toohs t’noD !tiaW“
,rehtruf flesmih ot gnirednop erofeB
ylnepo os ffulb sih gnillac enoemos fo tcepsorp ehT
,sdnopser ehs ,sraet eht kcab gnithgiF
.sreffo ym detcejer syawla eh …tuB
”?eybdoog yas tsael ta ot gniog toN“ ,stnap ehS
.eci yreppils niht eht etagivan ot xnyL sselriah eht rof stiaw eh sa stekcop sih ni stsif sih gnihcnelc ,ecalp ni syats ymereJ  ”!pu tiaW“
,uoy ta kool tey dnA
segap aidem laicos sih no tuo mih thguos ohw eno eht saw ehS
,pu kcab sdnats ylwols ymereJ
,nwod skool repraH
!gniyl er’uoy wonk I
.snoitseuq ym gnirewsna tuoba woH
.ruf etihw dlo ruoy kcab nworg ev’uoY
,sksa ehS  .ssenetilop fo tuo gnilims ylyhs erofeb kool elbanoitseuq a sevig ehs
.gnissap ni nees evah dluoc ymereJ
.tliug fo sgnileef gnissessop tuohtiw meht hctapsid ot tluciffid oot semoceb semitemos ti
emit hguone pu tae snoitseuq dedne-nepo eht sepoh eh
?tib a rof klat dna tis ew t’nod yhw ,lleW“
,trihs-t dnab cihparG A  sivaD
,rentrap a ,esuoh a
!efil sih ni ecno
.ecno pu pils reven ot troffe na ni thginot rof srewsna tcefrep evig ot gnikees
,evael ot pu sdnats eh sa tsuJ
”.wohs doog ytterp a no tup yehT
”?ksa uoy od yhw ,oN“
.elbissop sa hcum sa ytitnedi ciripmav sih laecnoc ot tpmetta ot tnatropmi saw ti ,mih oT
,pu skaeps repraH
”.uoy erussa nac I
,ainnellim owt tuohguorht noitacinummoc dna yrnopaew fo stnemecnavda eht gnomA
.yrevocer sih stnemilpmoc dna yrots llams sih ot gnola sdon repraH
rehtegot spirt ssalc no tnew ew tuB
”.dehsinav eh fi erac dluow enoyna kniht t’ndid eH
erom ecno yteicos no gniyler trats ot evah ll’eh
.syad ni netae t’ndah dna rallod tsal sih ot nwod saw eH“
!ytitnedi sih gnimussa raf siht tnew uoy nehw toN
.retfa noos doolb sih fo ymereJ dlo eht deniard dah eh
,reddal eht sdrawot daeh ot dnuora snrut eh sA
.noitasrevnoc fo stcejbus gnitanimod eht era nerdlihc owt htiw enoemos gniees fo tcepsorp eht dna
.tcerroc yltsom er’uoY“
.mih xaler pleh ot sdioipo dna sevitades lufrewop emos mih evag I
,worruf sworbeye siH
,elcric laicos gnorts dna
,etartsnomed ot rovaedne llahs ew sa roF
.evael ot yrruh a ni raeppa ot gnitnaw ton
,tub tuo hcaer ot erom enod ev’dluoc I ,eruS
.emit s’repraH erofeb yaw dna dlo sedaced erew daeh sih otni pop taht stca cisum eht semitemoS
.ecalp reporp rieht ni niamer srats eht
.evael sih htiw deecorp ot
,selahni ylprahs repraH
,seunitnoc dna esrup reh ni nug eht yawa sehsats ehS
!semit elpitlum dnah-thgir ruoy gnisu uoy was I ,thgir s’tahT
?naem uoy od tahW“
?gniciton enoyna tuohtiw ytitnedi s’esle enoemos emussa ot gnidneterp
.ereht dna neht thgir reh no tsaef dluow eh spahrep
.ytitnedi ciripmav sih yawa evig ylluf lliw os gniod tub
muisanmyg eht fo edis eht ot dnuorg yci niht eht no sedilg repraH
.txen evom dluohs eh erehw ot sa etalpmetnoc ot
,seunitnoc ymereJ
,eson reh hguorht sffuh repraH
.htuom sih sepacse ssih llams a sa ecnayonna htiw sliocer elzzum sih tub ,gninetaerht erutseg eht dnif t’ndid eH .lataf evorp dluow traeh sih gnittih tellub yarts a ,noitnem ot toN
.meht revo sehsaw ezeerb dloc a sa tekcaj yffulf reh ni elzzum reh sedih ehS
.spil sih snethgit eh sa dnim sih ni liorb segaugnal tnereffid net ni sdrow esruC
.dnatsrednu I“ ,sdon repraH
”?gniht a hcus od eh dluow yhW …yhW
,mih ecalper nac ydobon dnA
,ynnuf s’ti kniht uoy oD
si …ton si eh gniht eno eht ,eb thgim eh esle revetahw
.keew eht revo hcum uoy ot klat ot elba neeb t’nevaH
gnitirw sesu ohw
”!dne peed eht ffo enog ylraelc ev’uoY
ot tnaw t’ndid …dna
,ecaf reh revo dnah sih gnivaw dna lleps sisonpyh sih gnitcane erofeB  ”…eht pord dna
teL“,htiw sdnopser repraH erofeb ssap ecnelis fo sdnoces wef A  ”.eno yrev ehT“
”.gnihtyreve dna etalp sih denaelc eH .os sseug I“
.mrah tsael eht edivorp dluow taht noitulos a ot emoc ot gniyrt dnuora secap eH
,regrub nocab eht ,sseug em
.skeew owt rednu tsuj ni doirep lainoloc s’yrtnuoc eht gnirud hsilgnE naciremA denrael dah eh ,lleH
.dnuorg eht ot sllaf redluohs thgir reh no esrup eht sa etalid slipup reH
,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer ,sivaD suiraD yb
”.no ssap mih pleh ot saw I egnahcxe ni dna
.noitasrevnoc ni mih gnigagne ni tseretni na sekat esle eno on ,feiler s’enilef eht oT
,eye s’ymereJ ot tnemevom elbaeciton ynit fo noitpecxe eht htiW
,noitullop thgil elttil os htiW
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
,ymereJ ta gnicnalg nopU
?ta gnitteg er’uoy tahw dnatsrednu t’nod I tuB“
.dnopser dluow eh fi wonk neve t'ndid I
.ynnuf t'nsi sihT“ ,pu stis ymereJ
.emit gnol a rof enola neeb s’eh taht tesno eht morf raelc saw ti tuB
.retal seitirohtua eht yb erutpac elbativeni sih erussa ylno dluow won eelf oT
emit ot emit morF“
!thgirla ,daed s’eH“
.reh rof snalp rehto sdloh llits ymereJ
,noitatnemucod tnaveler eht lla em evag eh ecnO
”.em gnidnif rof uoy knaht lleW
,em rof gnikool retfa nam dnik a ekil mees uoY
.ti htiw enod eb dna ecnetsixe dlo s’ymereJ fo yromem lla esare dluoc ylpmis eH
.nosrep tnereffid yletelpmoc a tsuj er’uoy …oN“
.redro ni noitautis sih teg mih dah dna ytiC kraP ot kcab mih koot I“ ,ekops ymereJ
.gniht a hcus od ot tluciffid ti sekam yteicos nredom
,ot netsil ylevissap ot noitasrevnoc llud tsom eht ton elihW
.loohcs retfa yduts ot dna hcnul rof mih etivni ot deirt I“
,uoy tuoba deirrow yllaer saw I .ymereJ
.keew tsap eht rof edis sih ta nroht tnatsnoc a neeb s’ehs dna
.dnab taht detah syawla dna trihs taht raew reven dluow eh ,lla fo tsriF
,seidegart fo gnirts a si efil s’nosrep a erehw s’ymereJ ekil snoitautis rof tuB
.efil sih fo tnemom tsewol eht ta
”.baher ni elihw ruf ruoy fo knuhc doog a gniddehs erew uoy
”.nameltneg enif yrev a saw eh erus m’I .uoy knahT“
”.uoy rof gnikool erew sdneirf ruoy fo wef A
,elkcuhc eht serahs ymereJ
,redluohs reh no esrup llams eht fo parts eht gnitsujdA
,sksa repraH ,seye sih otni kool yltcerid ot gninruT  ”?taht
.llafthgin gnirud yxalag tsav eht gniyduts s'ti
”?sih fo dneirflrig tsap a neeb evah ot neppah t'ndluow uoy ,ecnahc yna yB“
,yks thgin eht otni pu gniratS
?sliated llams hcus no pu dekcip evah dluoc ehs woh srednow eH
,dworc a fo wor tnorf eht nI
”.traeh ym ni ecalp a evah syawla ll’eh dnA
!erehwyna gniog ton er’uoY“ ,slley ehS
,egde no sdnats eH
”.tib elttil a egnahc em edam taht dnA
.etats sisonpyh eht fo tuo reh gnippans erofeb dnammoc tsal eno redro ylpmis ot si tfel si taht lla
,thginot rof niaga sknahT
.syadawon gniod si ymereJ woh tuoba seiriuqni reh rewsna dluow eh ,gninruter nopU
,sworbeye reh sworruf repraH
.edulcnoc ot tneve eht rof
”?strecnoc ot tuo daeh llits uoy oD
.ecnarF fo noitarebiL eht fo htamretfa eht ni reidlos naciremA na eb ot mih swohs ti
.ymereJ wen eht ot revo gnihtyreve gnissap erofeb noitnem ot deliaf eh gnihtemoS
.noisufnoc fo etats a ni daeh reh sbur ylthgil ehS
.reidlos nwonknu na sa mih was ylpmis cilbup eht fo tsom tub
.elims llams a gnihsalf elihw lasoporp reh ot seerga eh
,tnemtraped ygrene eht ni srovaedne reerac reh
)seirotsd2( ta
.sregnif xedni owt dna bmuht a pu gnidloh
”?nesraL ymereJ laer eht ot deneppah tahW
em deknaht tsuj eH“
rehtaf deltnurgsid s’ymereJ morf swen gniviecer retfa noitcidda htiw selggurts sih fo erawa llew saw ehS
”.sraey net tsal eht drah neeb s’ti …I
.sraey ytenin tsomla rof thguoht hcum ti nevig t’ndah eH
”!ssendam si siht ,repraH no emoC
.elbissop sa sselniap sa ssecorp eht ekam ot deirt enilef eht
,otohp a hcus fo ecnetsixe eht fo erawa saw eH
sdnah dab htiw tlaed gnitteg tpek tsuj eH
,metsys s’ymereJ dlo eht ni sdioipo dna sevitades lufrewop htiW
snoitpo ro ecnatsissa tuohtiw tfel eb ot
,egdelwonk sih fo tseb eht ot teY
taerter ot yawa gnikaerb trats seednetta eht fo wef a
.esrup reh hguorht gniggid repraH sraeh enilef eht
”.dne yrev eht llit mih htiw deyats I dnA
.mih sehcaorppa enilef rellams eht sa
,yks eht ta pu erats ot stis ymereJ nehw dnA
semoceb ecnelis eht erofeB
,anosrep wen siht nI
.ssecorp eht htiw spleh ylniatrec gnivirra ot roirp metsys sih ni ezoob emos gnivah hguohT
.stpure gnab llams a
nemow otni t’nsaw eh demussa syawla I
.secnatsmucric emertxe erom ni dna snaps emit retrohs ni seititnedi demussa s’eh ,llaretfA
.reh htiw pu hctac ylkciuq ot noitatiseh on gniwohs ,spets ykcinif eht sdnecsa eH .dniheb esolc wollof ot ymereJ setivni dna reddal ytsur eht srewol ehs ,pu flesreh porp ot retspmud ybraen a gnisU
.niaga evom ot deen yllautneve ll’eh
”…mubla oiduts eht sa doog sa reven era sgnos fo snoisrev evil eht skniht dna meht setah eH
.tseuqer eht gniraeh nopu taorht sih morf tuo speerc tsomla ssih yratnulovni nA
.yteicos fo segnirf eht no evil ot mih rof wolla regnol on lliw hcet hcuS
.ecnesba reh eciton ot elpoep rof hguone tnatropmi oot eb llits dluow repraH
”…daed gnikcuf s’eH
,daeh sih fo kcab eht sehctarcs ymereJ
rats a was eh semit fo lufdnah llams a ylno erew erehT
,daeh sih swob ymereJ
.etaicossa yldneirf eno gnivah
,ksat eht gnitelpmoc nopU
,sivaD suiraD yb ”ycaripsnoC“
.tuo mih hcraes ot srehto eripsni dluoc yldrazahpah os gniod hguohT
.rewsna reporp a no selttes yllanif dnim sih ,drawkwa
.rellat elttil a nettog ev’uoy
,tol gnikrap eht ssorca tsuj amitlA nassiN nwod-nur sih ees dluoc eH
dneps eh did woH“
enod si enod s’tahw tuB
.sselnoitom dnats-owt eht sa ria daed eht sllif ecnelis yvaeh A  ”…ees I“
?yako ,emit eht ta ffuts fo tol a hguorht gniog saw I“
smsirennam s’ymereJ dlo no snwad eh
.ssalg reh llifer ot gnireffo yb repraH no noisserpmi evitisop a evael neve ot sepoh eH
s’tahW“  ”.uoy ksa ot detnaw syawla ev’I gniht eno tsuj s’ereht …haeY“
”!ekaw llahs uoy won …taht htiW
egap yrrufoS sih dna goDdliWD2@ rettiwt no mih wollof nac uoY.sevitcepsrep
,yawyna oS“ ,seunitnoc ehS
.aissuR dellac won ecalp a ni htuoy sih morf snoitalletsnoc wef a gnizingocer
”!dneirf ym htiw enod uoy evah tahW
.tuo ruop snoitome fo edacsac a sa skeehc reh morf sraet eht yawa sepiw repraH  ”…ebyam tsuj
”!flesym llits m’I ?no uoy era tahW
.sgniht ni etsat sih gnignahc rof hcum neeb reven s’eh ,thgir er’uoY“
.lla si uoy no pu kcehc ot detnaw tsuJ“ ,skrims repraH
,evaw llams a sevig eH
.mra sih nwod elzzird doolb fo skceps wef a sa niap ni revo sleek ymereJ
etaicossa esolc ylsuoiverp a fo noitcaretni llams a sa elpmis sa gnihtemos taht serugif ymereJ
.ni erusolc dnif ot eeL repraH rof hturt fo mucidom
.sraet eht yawa epiw ot ecaf reh ot pu wap dnah tfel reh gnidloh
”?uoy ot emag a tsuj siht sI
.em fo yllis woh …hO“ ,sdon repraH
”ycaripsnoC“ saw sihT
”?knird a teg ew tuoba woH
.loohcs hgih ni kcab wonk ot desu I enoemos fo em dnimer uoY
ytilicaf tnemnrevog a ta tnemyolpme reh rof t’nerew ti fI
.pleh rof tuo hcaer ot demahsa oot leef netfo s’ymereJ ekil snoitautis ralimis ni …elpoeP“
,gnikaeps erofeb ylfeirb srednop ymereJ     ”?yad tsal sih
,sevirra thgindim nehW
.noitseuq eht yb kcaba nekat
”!erom gnihton ,gniod ym lla saw sihT
.duolc latigid reh dna
,epacse ot tsim fo duolc a otni tfihsepahs dluoc eH
”.ssim thgin efas a evah ,melborp oN“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sraet revo-tfel reh hguorht selkcuhc repraH
,eson sih hguorht shgis ymereJ
.hguoht uoy no doog kool seod tI .riaf ,riaF“
?wonk uoy das tsuj s’tI“
.niatrec rof wonk ton yam I“
;reilrae uoy fo koot I erutcip tahT !ton er’uoy tuB“
?ti yb naem ylbissop dluoc ehs tahw srednow eH
.elcihev sih rof tuokool eht no ecilop eht htiw raf levart t’ndluoc eh wenk ymereJ ,esac rehtie nI
.kcul sih no nwod ylurt saw eh fi em degassem ev’dluoc eH
”.semitemos smraerif ni tseretni sih htiw evissesbo elttil a fi
,seilper ymereJ ,kcab gninrut tuohtiW
”?no gnissap erofeb
”?loohcs ta sdneirf ekam ot yrt reve eh diD“
,secnatsmucric tsom ni mih llik t’ndluow stellub elihW
srehto tnacifingis ro sdneirf esolc sevlesmeht redisnoc ohw elpoep ylno ,yllausU
.pu gnihsinif noos dnuow redluohs sih htiw delaeh si dnah sih gniciton
.mih fo serutcip dna soediv latnedicni sseltnuoc ni nees sa sserpxe dluow ymereJ dlo eht taht seuc laicos tcerroc eht ffo sevig eH
,noisufnoc fo kool a sehsalf ymereJ
,noitalever eht nopu thgirf ni nekahs sdnah siH
,pil thgir sih fo renroc eht sguh elims llams A
.peels sih ni yllufecaep yawa dessap gnivah nesraL ymereJ rebmemer llahs uoY
.redluohs tfel sih sezarg dna
.segareveb dna skcans emos no enid yeht sa mih swollof ylkciuq dna sdon ehS
,egdun woble tfos a gniviG
,ylevisnefed mra tfel sih pu stup ymereJ
.tcepsus reve dluoc ehs tahw srednow eh dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
xnyhps htooms reH
,enilef eht rof ciglatson ylegnarts si thgis ehT
”?rof gnikrow uoy era ohw ,ffo tsriF
.stibah sih egnahc dna
traehteews a syawla saw eH
.saw ylniatrec eh ,haeY“
,dneirf doog a erew yllaer uoy fI
.kcen desopxe ylknirw reh morf doolb eht gnimusnoc tuoba ezisatnaf ymereJ sekam
euc sih sekat ymereJ
,odaroloC ot drawtsae gniog sredisnoc ymereJ
ytinutroppo fo stekcop elbaton fo srepsihw sraeh eH
,draeh I tsaL ?wonk uoy
,etareneger ot sdnuow sih morf niks dna elcsum eht rof gnitiaw elihW
,teews saw eh thguoht I
mlap sih hguorht secreip remmah toh netlom a fo dne prahs eht ekil sleef tahW
,nesraL ymereJ  .treseD eht morf
.don daeh llams a sevig dna
,daeh sih stlit ymereJ
”.edud ,uoy rof llew gniog era sgniht taht ecin tsuj s’tI
.regnarts dnik ,gnihtemos uoy llet ot tnaw I …og uoy erofeB“
.ecnedicnioc a fo erom gnihton eb ot eman sih htiw serutaef sih gnilbmeser enoyna dragersid llahs uoY
.meht dnuora elpoep eht ot devarped tca dna
.dne na ot emoc ot deen lliw
ylevissimbus srae sih sdlof eH
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa reeuq kcalb a
.ssensuovren fo sngis lacisyhp yna yalpsid ot ton seirt enilef eht
”?ees ot tuo og uoy did sdnab hcihw ,hO“
gnihtyna yas eh diD“
.noitcerid taht ni daeh ot sesoohc os eh fi seitic rojam diova ot dnim ni gnipeek
,dworc esraps eht syevrus enilef yrruf etihw ehT
,no erow thgin eht sA
kcab emac I nehW
.seitiliba gnilaeh euqinu sih ot eud ymereJ wen eht no tceffe on dah doolb eht hguorht gnisruoc enicidem ehT
”?eadnus a dna ,seirf
renroc eht ni sklus eh ,won roF
.srehto yb nopu deksa sselnu eman sih noitnem ot tsrif eht eb reven llahs uoy dnA
.gnorw ylraelc s’eh lleW“
ymereJ sperp ti sa thgis emoclew a si gnitixe elpoep fo ngis eht tuB
”.laem tsal reporp a dah eh erus edam I
.ylthgils os reve tfihs ot srats emos sesuac sraey derdnuh wef a
.eromyna efil fo emag eht yalp
.sraey fo sderdnuh revo rof detavitluc sah eh lliks a si dnammoc no hsulb ot elba gnieB
.sevitcepsrep gniticxe dna wen ecneirepxe ot sredaer emirp ot yaw a sa
!ymereJ ym ekil gnihton er’uoy tub
!siht htiw yawa teg nac uoy gnikniht rof yzarc er’uoY“ ,selffins repraH
.eman sih tuo tuohs eciov railimaf a draeh eh
,teiuq ,ecin a dnif ot retcarahc s’anosrep demussa sih ni eb dluow ti
.tpurretni ot tnaw t’ndid I dna ysub erew uoy ekil dekool ,yrroS“
”.taht noitnem ot detnaw I os
!dednah-tfel neeb syawla s’eh ,drihT
meht fo draeh reveN ?hO“
,anosrep sih otni htnom a tsuj htiw nevE
,mra tfel reh htaenrednu nug eht skcut ehS
,mih morf denrut daeh reh speek repraH
ecaf yldneirf a naht erom gnihton si eeL repraH
,eciov peed a ni skaeps eH
,rehtruf yna srednop eh erofeB
.skeew wef tsap eht margorp pihsrosnops a hguorht cinilc enodahtem a hguorht tnew eh woh snialpxe ymereJ .oga htnom a
,noitaudarg retfa yawa devom eh nehW
”!uoy ekil tsitra noc paehc a neve ton
noitasrevnoc erom rof ni mih hsif ot stpmetta erutaerc siht tcaf erem eht tsuJ
.ytitnedi sih htiw kcul em dehsiw dna
.netfo seton degnahcxe dna
.neht kcab mih ot noitnetta yna diap ydobon taht thguoht syawla ymereJ
.nosniboR repraH eno fo hcuot eht gnizingocer
,daeh sih fo kcab eht sbur eH
,erehpsimeh nrehtron eht ni sniamer eh sa gnol oS
”!llehs ruoy fo tuo gnimoc ,uoy ta kooL
”!repraH ,em ot ecno uoy denoitnem reven eh emoc woH
,gnineve eht fo tser eht rof reh gnitcartsid fo sepoh eht nI
gnireffus s’eh wonk ot desoppus I saw woh
.elbissop eb t’nac tahT“ ,stroter repraH
.eno tnerruc sih otni deximretni s’anosrep tsap sih fo emos gnivah flesmih sdnif eh ,siht ekil seiriuqni neddus htiW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY ..treseD eht morf
.eson sih hguorht hgis llams a tuo stel ymereJ
”?enigami I ,08-I ffo eno ehT“
.sregruB nworC ,ecalp etirovaf sih ta tae ot tuo mih koot I“
.egdelwonk fo aidepolcycne sih hguorht gnilcyc ,dnoces a fo hsalf a rof pil sih fo renroc eht setib ymereJ
”.uoy wonk neve t’nod I ekil s’tI
”?meht detah syawla uoy thguohT
mih fo erutcip a ekat ot esrup llams reh hguorht sgid dna selkcuhc ehS
retteb nettog ev’uoy dalg m’I“
.soirt fo stekcop otni gnikaerb erew elpoep woh gniciton
.repraH ,uoy ees ot doog syawla s’tI .esruoc fO“
,gniht eht s’ereh tuB“ ,pu stis repraH
.tuo pees ot swalc sih fo wef a sesuac
.ytisrevinu llams a rof hcraeser fo emitefil sih gnitubirtnoc dna
,eerged ssenisub reh fo seicacirtni eht tuoba gninraeL
…ytitnedi wen a rof gnikool mih ot emac I
”.srevol tsap ro sdneirf yna denoitnem reven ,ylniatreC
”?taht retfa deneppah tahW
.seman tnereffid rednu shpargotohp redlo ynam ni uoy dewohs ti dna ppa IA na hguorht ti nar I
remonortsA na gnimoceb setalpmetnoc eh
”.kcart no kcab gnitteg yllanif si efil ym ekil sleef
.seilppus gnivom wef a htiw dekcap ydaerla
”?od uoy did htrae no tahW …doG hO“
sedaced eerht rof yawa edih ot mih wolla lliw taht gnihtemoS
.epyt evisulcer eht syawla saw eH“
.evird rof sedapacse suoiverp sih gnisu flesmih erussa ot seirt yllatnem eH
,regnif sih fo pans a htiW
…kcuF“ ,selffins repraH
…ebyam taht thguoht tsuj I
.derutpac gnieb dna
”.dnekeew doog a no sdnal ti fi
.elims tfos a gnisserpxe
.foor muisanmyg eht no gnizagrats erew uoY“ ,sdnopser ymereJ
.niaga sisonpyh sih gnitpmetta erofeb ytiliba sih fo tseb eht ot reh gnitacalp no snalp eh ,teef sih no gniknihT
.sdeen ymereJ taht lla si srekaens nwod-nur dna ,snaej dlo
.noinuer loohcs hgih luftnevenu eht deppiks gnol ev’dluow eh
emos htiw stneve fo yrotsih etanretla na evaew ot sediced eh
.htiw laed ot smurdnunoc ytsan llits erew yeht
.htaerb sih no ti gnihctac seidob ysub nwot-llams eht fo tser eht tuohtiw ehtnisba emos ni kaens dluoc eh ylno fI
.tixe ybraen eht hguorht pils ot seirt dna
,sredluohs sih sgurhs ymereJ
?reilrae mih ot tuo dehcaer uoy t’ndah yhw neht
,ralimis kool yam uoY
elims mraw a fo tca eht pu sretsum eH
.elbissop eb t’nac taht …oN“
.esac laiceps a si nesraL ymereJ tub ,yrotsih tuohguorht ega yreve ni
.reddal latem ytekcir a ot ymereJ sdael dna
,ytilautca ni taht tcaf eht sedih yllanoitnetni ymereJ
.noitacude ym eusrup ot yawa devom I
,thguoht emos esnopser sih gnivig retfa hguohT
.od uoy tahw no sdnepeD“
,ydob s’dlo raey ytriht a ni kcuts yllauteprep gnieb hguohT
,yltfiws reh sllik eh fi neve dnA
”.egnahc ot dewolla era setsat ym ,yeh tuB
”?wonk uoy ,dnim s’enoemos daer t’nac I
.htuoy loohcs hgih ruoy gnirud mih sdrawot yldnik gnitca ni ecalos ekat llahs uoY
”.erehwesle seitinutroppo retteb dnuof eh thguoht I
,sdnoces wef a rof gnirednoP
,ymereJ laer eht t’nerew uoy eciton t’ndid srehto eht fi nevE
.ni syad sih fo tser eht dneps ot aera larur dna
,yawa klaw ymereJ gnihctaW
.no eman sih tsil ot pu tes dah eh krowrepap tneluduarf hguorht deifirev eb dluow repraH ot nevig sliated yna dnA
,pu skrep liat s’repraH
.srewsna thgir desoppus s’ymereJ laer eht ot sesnopser gnitcilfnoc evig ot mih dael dluow taht soiranecs evisnetxe nettirw sah ehS .seton reh ni
.noitnetta lluf ta dnats ydob s’enilef eht sehctaw eh
!nwod wols aohw ,aohW“ ,stroter eH
ohadI hguorht-ssap llams a gnikat setalpmetnoc osla eh ,niaga nehT
”?nesraL ymereJ laer eht htiw enod uoy evah tahW“
.snoitatcepxe laicos rehto fo dairym a gniteem ro
,tuo sraelc ylwols moor eht fo flah retfA
,mra reh sevaw repraH
.2 raW dlroW gnirud mih fo hpargotohp dlo na si tsom eht mih sesirprus taht eno eht tuB
modeerf neewteb ecnereffid eht naem dluow setunim wef a rof gnillats spahreP
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.ytrap noinuer loohcs hgih eht htiw ecnatsissa rof mih deksa dna
,lleps peels peed eht gnidulcnoc retfA
.daeh sih ta thgiarts gnitniop nug eht gniciton
.revo gnillaf morf flesreh gnihctac erofeb ecalp ni selbmuts repraH
yawaevig daed a syawla si wapdnah
,gniyas erofeb sessih repraH
.gninnigeb eht ecnis dnim sih ni gniregnil neeb s’taht noitseuq a sksa yllanif eh
.lleps eht gnikaerb retfa ecno naht erom reh ezitonpyh tonnac eh dnA
”?wonk uoy ,sraey net ni enoemos ot neppah nac tol A
,etilop eb ot erised eht ni hguohT
,wap dnah-thgir sih stfil ymereJ
.yxalag railimaf eht erolpxe dna rednaw seye sih stel eh
.nesraL ymereJ otni snoitagitsevni tnecer ruoy ron
,niap eht hguorht gnitnurG
,pu skaeps ymereJ
!SELDI ot denetsil uoy wonk t’ndid
.gnineve eht rof
,daeh reh sekahs repraH
,klaw tsaf dluoc eh erofeB
?neeb uoy evah woh
.ecaf sih fo slievnu erawtfos IA eht sotohp desoppus eht ssorca emac eh
,trihs eht ekil I
suiraD yb ”ycaripsnoC“
.ygolonhcet IA ni stnemecnavda eht si tsom eht mih snethgirf yllaer tahw
emitefil eritne sih tuohguorht lavivrus sih derusne ylsuoiverp taht secitcarp eht taht mih no snwad tI
rof hguohT .htrae eht deklaw s'eh seirutnec eht ni avonrepus a otni nrut
,noitnem ot toN .ekat ro evig
.mih ot hctam tcerid a erew sotohp eht fo ytirojam eht taht gnirevocsid
,flesmih senimaxe ymereJ
,puY“ ,sdon ymereJ
.gab reh eveirter ot revo sklaw ymereJ
,daeh sih sekahs ymereJ
.enohptrams s’enilef eht ot ssecca niag ot sdnammoc nrets wef a sekat ylno tI
,enohptrams reh tuo sllup ehS
,pu skaeps repraH
.elkcuhc elbidua na tuo gnittel
trecnoc a ot neeb reven s’eh ,yltsaL
.ezagrats ot tluciffid ti sekam seitic rojam ni noitullop thgil ,sraey derdnuh tsal eht
.mih yonna ot tnaw t’ndid dna
,selggig repraH  ”!nuf saw ti
.stnemilpmoc htiw derewohs gnieb nehw puc sih htiw eson gnihsulb thgirb sih sedih dna
.snoitseuq dedne nepo ni reh segagne eh
.kcen sih hguorht llihc dab a tnes hpargotohp a hcus nwod kcart ot hguone decnavda si erawtfos noitingocer laicaf taht tcepsorp ehT
.nuf ytterp sdnuos taht tub
.knird reh gnillifer yltfiws erofeb dnah thgir sih htiw ti psarg ot tuo sehcaer eh ,seerga ehs nehW
,reh niatretne ot thgin tsal
.mih ta yltcerid ti stniop dna revlover llams a tuo sllup ehS
,eman wen a htiw nwot rehtona ot evom ylpmis dluoc eh erehw dlo fo syad eht ekilnU
.retteb nettog ev’I
,sdnammoc tsal sih srehsu ymereJ
,nekat sah ehs seton evisnetxe eht yb kcaba nekat si ymereJ
.noos eerged etaicossa ruoy gnitteg er’uoY
.mih htiw erew yllaer uoy sseug I
.tcatnoc eye lla gnidiova
”.regrub sih rof seotamot on dah eh tuB
.elbarelot tahwemos noitcnuj laicos eht ekam dluow taht gnivaH
efil reh fo sgnineppah eht tuoba no elttar ot repraH swolla ymereJ
.mih tuoba tol a wonk uoy taht tsuJ“ ,sgurhs eH
,dnim sih ni sdrow eht gnitalumroF
,noissapmoc fo tca erar a nI
,pu skrep enilef ehT
;mih ssim ot gniog m’I .did I
?gniod er’uoy kniht uoy od kcuf eht tahW“ ,stroter ymereJ
,mih sdrawot yltcerid ezag reh snrut yllanif repraH nehW
.sraey net tsap eht rof
,tnatsnoc railimaf eno si ereht fI
,selims yltfos eH  ”.pu hctac ot detnaW
,gniggid rehtruf htiw dnA
.ereht gnisuoh elbadroffa dna
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
keew siht snoitasrevnoc roirp ruo fo yromem on evah llahs uoY“
.erom ecno lleps msitonpyh sih nommus ot pu wap dnah thgir sih sgnirb ymereJ
.nam doog a saw eh
.yks dnarg yllufituaeb eht nopu ezag ot ytinutroppo eht sah ymereJ
”!tuo siht klat s’teL