,detroter wodahS ”!elbaroda os kool uoy sekam tsuj taf yppup taht pu gnipeek dnA“
.deunitnoc eulB ”,rettam t’nod tI“
.sevlesmeht niatnoc ot deirt yeht sa sedis rieht otni swap rieht gniggid
,ereh hcum edivid t’ndid secnef tekcip etihw ehT
,tsaot no odacova no yenom rieht dneps
”!niaga mih raen rettil ym gnittel ton m’I !elbacipsed yletulosbA“
- ti tuoba yltnassecni ruf reh dewalc ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mrala ni thgirpu dekcirp srae
.taem pu evig ot erised ym ro ,gnitnuh ni tseretnisid ym edih
.daeh reh gnikcoc ,deksa eulB
,srewsna wef dah I
,ksed eht tsniaga swalc deppihc sih gnippat
,sdrow rieht ni gniknird
.ekatsim fo tros emos saw ti ekil rehto hcae ta yldetraeh-flah gnippans
.gnitacidni tuohtiw enal elddim eht otni devrews ohw reed a ta nroh reh gnidnuos
.hguoht looc em tpek tI
.hteet reh neewteb gnicreip pil reh tib ehs sa elzzum ym no kool desserpminu eht gnihctac ,em desaet eulB
.roolf eht tsniaga gniparcs swalc ,delruc seot yM
.srehto lla gnilfits
”!zeeG“ .deilper wodahS
”.tae t’ndluohs flow a taht sdoof fo tsil eht gniticer yrt ,dab s’taht kniht uoY“ .erows wodahS
.lwoh ot tuoba fi sa kcen sih gnihcra
.hteet s’eulB ot kcen sih gnisopxe
.em ot gnirepsihw ,nwod em gnittap
,sevooh gniddolp s’nosnhoJ .rM gnitatimI
!kcis erew uoy dias nosremE“
.noigatnoc eht tuoba deirc yeht sa stnerap rieht rof tuo gnikeirhs
,hteet sih derab ro delworg eh ylduol woh rettam on dna
,daeha ylteiuq gnikoj dna gnihgual meht raeh dluoc I
”,eulB ,msi-lau-div-id-nI“
,deffuh ehS ”?sessalc-flow diputs esoht ni taht uoy hcaet yeht
.seye ym gnillor ,deilper I
,sllaw kcirb-der eht tsniaga llab a gnikcik
.ruf rof detalumrof yllaiceps ,htgnerts artxE“
.loohcs eht tfel tey t’ndah llits ohw
”?hsaw reve eh seoD“ .llems eht yawa epiw ot gniyrt
”.sevlesmeht yerp nwod ekat t’ndluoc yeht esuaceb
.enilpicsid fo dohtem lamirp taht deirt eh sa taem nettor fo knats htaerb sih
-“         .yltneg tuons ym gnippat
.enigne eht gnippots dna yawevird eht otni pu gninrut
,no gnilbmar hsinif ot flow dlo yllems eht rof gnitiaw
,tliub tnemeticxe ym sa gnilbmert morf sdnah ym peek ot gniyrt ,pil ym tib I
.em ot kcab gninrut ,deunitnoc eh
”!skeew rof tsal ll’ti esiwrehto
.no reh gnigde ,deilper I
,su hguorht dewolf taht tnemeticxe eht tnev ot gnilggurts ,nwod dna pu depmuj ew sa secaf rieht revo sdnah rieht gnidloh
.ecnaraeppa reh pu gnipeek otni troffe ssel dna ssel tup d’ehs
,flow a ekil hcum os gnieb tuoba klat sih lla rof ,drofloW
dna sdleif hguorht gnitnirps yad eht tneps eW
,taorht ym pu tperc yrotciv emos eralced ot ,tuohs ot egru ehT
,yldeticxe dekrab eulB ”!meht naem uoy
”-dna ekatsim eno tsuJ“
;wonk ot deen t’ndid
,elzzum reh delknirw ehs
”?redlo teg I nehw lruc liat ym lliW“
”.su tuoba deson-ytniop lla teg sevlow ynam oot
pu wodniw eht dehsup I
,tsud yvaeh ekil dereyal edisni ria eht ;knats tI
.sreltna sih ffo neetevlev eht gniparcs tuoba tnew eh sa dias eh
”.ytilatnem kcap drawyaw ruoy esrever ot gniyrt lissof emos yb worran dna thgiarts eht ot kcab dekniwdooh eb ot hguone bmud ton s’eH“
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT hguorht gnitirw rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,hcrop eht otno tuo deppets I sa sgel ym ni romert eht edih ot deirt I
,drawrof gnipeerC
,rehtaf emoceb tsuj dah rehtaf-neD retfA
.seiksuh fo soahc eritne na tub
,yaweerf eht no ciffart ni kcuts llits saw ehs taht detxet d’ehs
,tnelis deyats I tub
.swap gninniht sih htiw emarf lateleks sih pu gnipporp
,flesreh ot rettum dna sevlow esoht htiw gnola don dluow rehtom-neD dnA
”.god yrutnec ts12 laer a
.setteragic fo llems eht dna
- semit lla ta rood eht ot kcab sih gnipeek
,resolc denael eH
.ti gniraew neve er’uoy wonk t’now yeht os
.hteet ym fo hsalf a htiw ti no nwod gnipmahc erofeb
,dekrab ehs ”,ti evorp ot tog s’rehcaet - gnihtemos llems yeht fi neve dna
,won detcefni erew yeht tub ,redro llitsni ot deirt eh sa detuohs dna deirc dna dehgual yehT
goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.skool rieht etipsed etarobale ot gnisufer ,derettum I
”!liat ruoy gnilruc pots dnA“
.pu em kcip ot emac eh nehw yaw taht tnew syawla rehtaF-neD dna
.kool gnidlocs a etam reh tohs wodahS
”,noitacude ruoy ot
,me‘ htiw ytilatnem kcap on s’erehT
,ti tuohtiw evil rehtar dluow spup uoy teY
,dias ehs ”,won dnatsrednu ot uoy tcepxe t’nod I“         ”-tuB“
- hpmuirt ni hgih liat ym dloh ot tnemom taht koot I
.dehctiwt liat yM
,neht neve dna - walf-eneg taht tuo koot yeht seiceps ruo edam yeht nehW ?tahW“
”-esuoh s'rehcaet ruoy otni kaens ot sruoy fo slliks flow esoht esu uoy fi“
sah neve eh desirprus m’I“
”,su htiw tuo gnignah naht rehtar
.mra eht no yksuh eht gnihcnup
.desufnoc ,eugnot sih tib flow etihw ehT ”!liat s’god a s’taht tuB“
,taews fo gnikeer dna detlep-yddum
ssalc eht ta tuo kcab gnirats
.dettimbus d’I eveileb mih tel t’ndluow I .lautum saw egnahcxe ruo erus edam I .em ta gniralg
,namuh dlo emos ekil gnirons no tpek eH
.flowafoS dna ,tenalpruF
,eson reh ssorca eugnot reh dellor ehs sa tuons reh ta gniwap
,issaveleT yb erutluC-retnuoC saw yrots sihT
.gnol saw yad yM“
.sgod gnieb ,ysae os ti dah yehT
”!nerdlihc ruo detcefni eH“
a evah t’ndid yehT
,meht tuoba ton s’ti ,emit tsal eht roF“
,srac s’tnerap rieht ot kcab deretlif yeht sa kcap eht fo tser eht gnirongI
”.rehtaf ruoy tuohtiw drah neeb tsuj s’tI“
.edistuo spordniar fo rettap gniworg eht ot gninetsil
.kcor a ekil tpels
?yad ruoy saw woH“
,gnicreip pil dna sthgilhgih eulb reh htiw gnilddif ,dennirg eulB
;tey devirra t’ndah rehtom-neD
.tsap deps yeht sa snobbir knip ekil ria eht ni gnivaw seugnot
,tauqs kramedart sih otni kcab gnillaf elzzum ,dehsinif eH
- sniev ruoy hguorht gniwolf ti leef uoy t’naC“
,lla retfa evitanretla reteiuq eht saw tahT
?flesruoy eb nac uoy nehw ,esle enoyreve ekil eb yhW
.yldniknu ton tub
sesroh fo dreh a tsap devaew I sa meht fo thgis gnisol
!noom eht ta gnilwoh naht rehtar gnippar
,evisserppo saw thgin eht fo taeh ehT
.gnihtyna od t’ndluow dna ,diputs saw sihT .seye ym gnillor
,kcap eht ot eurt eB
,parc ytilatnem kcap rieht ot ni evig t’nod uoY
.swap ym htaenrednu gnihcnurc tsur eht
,sub eht no enoemos raen neeb tsuj ev’dluoC“
,sksed eht dniheb llA
draggah erew sdileye sih
”,og I erofeb yawa tnecs eht llor ot luferac m’I tsael tA“
,tuo ekorb yeht nehT
,deunitnoc ehs ”,erehwyna morf nettog ev’dluoc tnecs tahT“
.sessalc diputs dnetta ot meht decrof taht stnerap suoixna ro ,dlohpu ot ycagel lacihtym
.drofloW ot rood txen devil ohw reed a
.rehtruf eugra ot tpmetta ot elituf saw ti wenk I
.yb delcyc yeht sa swodniw eht ta secaf ekam
frut fo sknuhc tuo gnikat dna gniwalc swap
hcrop eht fo pot no teg dluoc I
,delworg eH ”?lufrewop
.ruf tsehc sih gnineerp ,deggurhs wodahS
”.efil ni no gnitteg fo ecnahc yna evah ot tnaw uoy fi evaheb ot woh wonk ot tog ev’uoY“
.mih ta kcab derats ssalc eht sa
,pup eht ta gniralg ,delworg eh ”,oN“
.etteragic dedracsid sih eviver ot deirt ehs sa htuom reh fo tuo gnillol eugnot
.ria eht otni fo liart ekoms eht gnihctaw ,deffup eulB
.tnecs ym gnillems nopu ekaw t’ndluow flow dlo eht taht gnipoh
.liat sih nethgiarts ot
.resolc gnikaens ,derettum I
tnarodoed rieht fo tnecs teews eht thguac I
.detcerroc wodahS
- ksed ym no wap sih gnippals ,drawrof tpael eno dlo ehT
!erofeb eno eht dna - thgin tsal tnelis saw eh reve emit tsrif eht roF
- laref a sa gnorts sa flah llems fo esnes rieht sah flow a neve toN“
,KU eht ni gnivil retirw yrruf a si ohw
.wap ym gnikat ,delims ehs
,yltpurba desruc ehS
;selkna sih revo pu dellor dna ffo dekcik steehs deb eht
,thgilnoom eht morf tsujda ot seye ym rof tnemom a koot I
;meht dniheb tuoba gnibbob sliat suolucidir rieht htiw srodirroc eht gnola gnitnirps
.dehctiwt elzzum ym tub ,eugnot ym tib I
.elttil rof ekow eh dna ,yad dna thgin ,esuoh sih edistuo morf gnirons sih raeh dluoc uoY
,yb no deppiks dlrow eht fo tser eht sa rethgual eht ot gninetsil wodniw eht tuo gnirats yb meht tuoba wenk ylno I
,ti pu debmilc I fi taht hguone esolc
- egde no gnidnats selkcah emos teg ot hguone
.hguoht oot flow dlo eht ot nettog dah erutarepmet ehT
.deirc ehS ”!ti lortnoc t’nac uoy ,ti eciton neve t’nod uoy ,emoh ta emit eht lla ti od uoY“
em ekil flow yrutnec ts12 a gnihtyreve no erew snossel ehT
.noitneted otni thgiarts flesruoy gnidnal tuohtiw taht yas nac uoy ylduol woh ees ot emag taerg a saw syawla tI
,dehsinif wodahS ”,flesruoy gnieb tuoba tsuj s’ti
.taht dias eh nehw dehcnilf rehtoM-neD
”.pu sekaw eh nehw ecaf sih no kool eht ees ot tiaw t’nac I“
.sgnirts elbisivni yb tuat nward fi sa ,kcab dellup - gniltsirb
,em nioj ot ni nar wodahS dna eulB
,tas eh ,gnidnats fo daetsnI
.tnereffid on saw yadoT
,ffP“ .pu gnithgil dna reh morf eno gnibbarg ,deggurhs I
.flow reporp a ekil tsuj
s’tnerap rieht sdrawot dehsur sevlow regnuoy eht sa gnihctaw
.ruf ym otni tnecs yksuh dna ekoms etteragic eht gnikrow
”.gniht taht pu flesruoy luah dna barg nac uoy yaw on
”-taht syas wodahS
,smra s’rehto hcae gnihctulc
- delworg ehs ”,uoy tuoba s’ti
,ria eht ni deregnil tnemeticxe fo tnecs ehT
,htaerb peed a gnikaT
”?tuo tnahc uoy evah yeht parc eht taht sI“  .denaorg I
,derelloh wodahS ”,no emoC“
,snamuh ot sgniht esoht erew ew esuaceb detfilpu eb ot tsrif eht erew eW
.liat ylruc reh gniggaw
.tsal ta ,modeerf teewS
- stnecs ruo yawa dehsaw niar gniworg eht sa gnihgual
.derepsihw eulB ”...liat sih otni siht krow dnA“
.krims ym gnirahs ,deddon seiksuh eht htoB
,dehgis rehtoM-neD
.edisni krad saw tI
,ti seod kcap eht fo hguone fI .gnihtyreve
,hteet sih dettirg eH
,swaj sih edistuo thguac eugnot
,snoitidart duorp ruoy gninodnaba
.hcrul traeh ym tlef I
,meht deppirtstuo I sa
”?eromyna sessalc esoht ot em dnes t’now uoy naem siht seoD“
,ylduol gnikrab ,em dettops rehtoM-neD
!dnik deifidom fo tser eht ot retal neve dna
”.syad eseht daor eht no esool tel stoidi ynam ooT“
”,ti htiw od nac uoy tahw tuoba s’tI“
”erutlruC-retnuoC“ :yojne esaelP
,em ffo reh gnillup ,dehgis wodahS ”,tey retteb tuB“
.deifirtcele fi sa pu gnidnats selkcah reh no sthgilhgih yci eht ,deppans eulB
.smraerof sih no ruf fo skaerts kcalb eht tsniaga sthgilhgih neerg dna ednolb eht htiw gnilddif
.ecneitap ym gnisol ,deppans I
,llat doots dna rood eht tuo tpael I ,sruof lla no srodirroc eht nwod gniddikS
,dias flow dlo eht tahw etipseD
senimreted ytilatnem kcap taht si
,desaet wodahS ”,hcum os gnitae peek uoy fi ti morf eid llits nac uoy tub ,haeY“
,rettil llams rieht retfa
.egatireh rieht yb derettefnu
.senam rieht morf gnippird taews ytsum ,gnorts rieht ta eson ym gnilknirw
.rehtegot meht gnippans ,sreilp fo tes a dna revirdwercs a tuo gnippihw
.ezeerb thgils eht thguac yeht sa sdrawtuo gnilruc sniatruc
.sdaeh rieht dekcoc walc eht fo wor tnorf eritne eht ,nosinu nI
,stekcop reh otni gud yksuh ehT
.eson ym gnilknirw ,deksa I
.ni dekcik ytilatnem kcaP
ekil‘ ;yltnelis gnivom ecitcarp ew detsisni dah drofloW erehw snossel eht gnirebmemer ,gninnirg
”.rehcaet ruoy no egnever teg ot
,enoemos eb ot tnaw reve uoy fI“
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT  ta elbaliava ,”xoF eht tahW“
,em fo dloh debbarg ehS
,dias eh ”,erom deen uoy fi ti taews t’noD
”,evaheb ot eunitnoc uoy sa gnol sA“
dlot eb ot kcen ym fo ffurcs eht yb sroodni deggard saw I ,sdneirf ym htiw sesroh no pu gnikaens dna steews gnitae syadnuS ym gnidneps fo daetsni ,oS .yas yehT
”,stsaeb ’citsejam dna ,elbon ,dliw‘ gnieb htiw noissesbo detadtuo ruo no detrats em teg t’nod ,hgU“
.dik su fo eno er’uoy ,eno rof ,lleW“
hsibbur s’nam cirotsiherp dediar ohw seno eht era yehT
- su fo eno er’uoy wohs ot gnihtemos htiw pu emoc ev’ew kniht ew dna
.’looc‘ dna ’ygde‘ saw ti esuaceb
”,evaheb ot woh wonk I“ .deksa I
,denaom I ”,suoregnad os saw leg riah ezilaer t’ndid I“
,esor sliat s’kcap eht ,sriahc rieht dniheb morf tuo gnikop
*** .yad taht snossel eht tuoba em ksa t’ndid ehS
.tnemtneser dna regna ni ruf ym ta gnikcip
,did sevlow-non tahw ypoc ot erised erutammi emos morf emac
,moor eht fo tnorf eht ta doots eye eno dlo ehT
”?uoy no ekoms eht llems reve yeht t’noD“
;nepo wodniw a tfel d’eh hcrop tekcip-etihw eht fo edis eht ot ffO
moorssalc a ni pu depooc s’yadnuS ruoy dneps ot uoy gnicrof rof traf dlo yffuts taht hcaet ll’siht ,haeY“
.sdrawkcab ti gnilruc
srae ym gnippots no etartnecnoc ot daetsni gniyrt
.elbat edisdeb sih ssorca dnas fo sniarg ekil derettacs sllip gnipeels
”,ti ta peek uoy fi pu mih ekaw ll’uoY !hhS“
”!lergnom derutlucnu na ekil esle enoyreve gniypoc
.dewollof enoyreve dnA
si yrots s’yadot dna
,syad wef tsal eht rof ylroop neeb sah drofloW .rM taht erawa eb ton yam uoY“
esoom detlep-etihw a
,sehctap dlab sih no gniniarts ylbisiv snodnet
.flow ’reporp‘ a eb ot woh
;noitatiga ni dessap yad txen ehT
,detegdif yksuh ehT
.rood eht tuo deklaw eh sa epahs ypmurg
”.meht htiw gnivil pu dne tnaw uoy fi hsilgnE ruoy gnicitcarp emit erom dneps attog ev’uoY“
wodahS dna eulB htiw ruoh eht dneps ot ssalc tsal ym fo tuo gnikcud neve - htworgrednu delgnat
.ylper t’ndid I tub ,delims I
- !kraB !kraB !kraB - yawa gnikrab syawlA
taem fo sbals erar otni dekcut kcap eht fo tser eht elihw slitnel dna saepkcihc ym ta gnikcip gnineve taht tneps I
.mra ym gnizeeuqs ,delggig eulB ”,haeY“
”!redlo er’uoy nehw em knaht ll’uoY“ .deppans rehtom-neD ”!doog nwo ruoy rof sessalc eseht gniod er’uoY“
,worromot ssalc ni srennam emos nrael d’I taht sgnaf dettirg hguorht reyarp tnevref a edam ehs ,seye ym ni ssendliw lla
.flow a fo gnimoceb lli gnihtemos
”,ynnuf os eb annog si sihT“
yehT‘  .seussi rieht tuoba ylsseldne derevals yeht sa hteet reh tsniaga detsiwt eugnot
”!god a ekil tca ot woh meht thguat eH“
.thgiled htiw tuoba dekcilf ti sa
dir teg ot syad koot taht ruf ruoy ni tlahpsa fo knits eht tfel dna ,ysion
.moorssalc eht fo kcab eht ot detturts eh sa ruf sih gniwalc
,rood dleh eht hguorht depmil drofloW
,ekops sredle gnidlab eht revenehw srae reh detfil ehS
,ereht tas tsuj eh ,edarit lausu sih otni gnihcnual fo daetsnI
.nwo ym fo gnicreip a teg dluoc I os neetxis nrut ot tiaw t’ndluoc I dna ,dekool ehs woh devol yletulosba I
”?gnikniht uoy era tahW“
”,gnorw em teg t’nod ,swalf rieht tog evah snamuH“
”.msitlaudividni tuoba gniht gib siht tog ev’yeht
”.semit doog eht ekil ,niaga rehtegot tuo gnah lla nac ew neht
.gnar yllanif lleb eht taht noitavlas sa ti koot I
”?revir eht yb emoh gninnur ton er’ew emoc woH“
,dliw leef uoy t’nod
.edaf ot meht rof tiaw tub od dluoc ehs hcum t’nsaw ereht tub
,sehcnarb elttirb eht dnuor gnipeerc
.em htiw ni denioj yehT
.snroh meht gnikam
.deppans ehs ”,yad ruoy tuoba em rewsna uoy raeh ot ecin eb dluow tI“
.kcen ym tsniaga gnaf dewolley ,elgnis a gnisserp
,repapswen eht morf pu gnireep elzzum sih
tops nac ehs niks delknirw fo sehctap ynam woh gnitnuoc ,dnuora detrad yeht sa seye neerg reh wollof ot ysae s’ti
.em ot delggums wodahS seilppus gnimoorg ot sknaht
,llems on tog s’ti ,tey tseb dna rehtegot ruf ruoy eulg t’now ti ,tlep ruoy ni enihs eht peek ll’tI
,deugra I tahw derettam reven tI
.niht erew stlep rieht esuaceb serifpmac s’namuh eht sdrawot knuls ohw seno eht era yehT .swollof god A
,ti htiw pu swap ym gnirehtal
ruf ym ot retsul ylio taht tpek llits I esuaceb detarelot ylno teid a - nodnaba htiw
,eulB won gnireppay er’uoY“ ”-niart eht no
.derekcib stnerap rehto eht elihw em gnikahs ,denoitseuq ehs ”?deneppah tahW“
.erofeb yna naht rediw
.yrd dna yffup lla tuo gnikcits
,pool a gnihctac god a ekil ti hguorht elzzum ym dekop I
.sukcur lufituaeb a saw tI
,hguoht pu thguoht reve snamuh tniop tseB-“
.tnemeticxe ni gniltsirb
,thgir mih evres ll’tI“
,dekrab derF ”!enoyna ot neppah dluoc tI“
.liat ruoy gnidloh rof s’ohw dna ,s’erehw ,s’nehw ,s’woh eht ekil
”.hsibbur emos htiw kcab semoc yletaidemmi neht dna
”.sdnim riaf tog ev’yeht tub ,gniht a llems ro sruof no nur ton thgim yehT
.dekrab flow citcra gnuoy a ,eivetS
”?liaT-thgiartS huh deticxe taht toN“
.sdneirf ym teem ot emit suoicerp em evag taht os
latipsoh morf tuo emac ehs thgin eht ’snoitasrevnoc‘
.nus eht ot pu swap ym dleh I sa smra ym tuo gnihcterts
ygolohtna eht ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw yrots sihT
,deliatruc t’nsi ytilatnem kcap rieht fI“
.barc a ekil gnippetsedis yb ksed sih ot revo gnissorc
”!gnihtyna hguorht speels eh flesruoy dias uoy“
.ni yaw a rof gnikool gnidliub eht dnuora deggoj I
,daeh reh dehctarcs dna dehgis eulB
.ronaemed lausu sih fo yna tuohtiw flesmih gnidloh
!derimda dna deraef erew ew stsaeb sA“
.dennirg yksuh eht
enohpelet eht fo dne eht ta eciov a emaceb eh ,gnihtyreve etipsed dna
;nossel tsrif yrev sih morf siht derebmemer I
.aneyh a ekil derekcins eulB
.gniffins ,gnikrab ,gnilwoh ,gnitib s’taht
”.meht fo eno s’etalocohC“ .desuap I
,gniht eht s’ereh tuB
,draobetihw eht ot kcab edorts dna swaj sih deppans redle eht ,deifsitaS
.gninworf ,kcab dellup ehS
.noom eht fo sesahp eht deziromem evah ot thguo ehs woh tuoba
”,oot lruc a htiw pu uoy leg ot looc ytterp eb d’ti thguoht ew ,os
.god nommoc a ekil kcab tneb liat sih htiw ereh saw
tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’eW“ .riah s’namuh a ekil elzzum dna redluohs sih ssorca nwod deliart yeht os enam sih ni sthgilhgih neerg dna ednolb eht htiw gnilddif
,smug sih ssorca eugnot sih gninnur ,desuap eH
.eunevA rezagratS rof ngis eht rednu ffo denrut ehs sa
- stnerap rieht naht rewol sehcni owt snaej rieht raew dna
.nur revir eht nekat evah dluohS
.ereh em tnes rehtom-ned yhw nosaer niam eht demrof taht sdneirf ym saw ti ,hturt nI
,leg eht tuo koot I
- ’egaugnal lanoitidart‘ rO
,os gniod ni dna pu gnidnats ,dednammoc eh
.swap sih otni gnihgis ,denworf yksuh kcalb ehT
.kcen ym tsniaga elzzum derehtiw sih gnisserp
.srekcits deleep-flah dna
- wodahS dna eulB - sdneirf ym gnihctaw
.tnereffid gnieb tuoba saw tI
.netfo dna ylthgil speels flow eurt a
”!klat I nehw pu em tuhs ’na yrt t’nod nehT“
.yadot nossel ruoy rof yadot ni gnimoc no detsisni sah eh revewoh
.srae reh gnidlof ,pil reh gnitib
”.me‘ htiw evil ydaerla uoy ,uoy rof ysae s’tI“
- ecnahc a toN“
,edis sih no yal eH
”,eno wen a em ewo uoY“
nehW‘  .em detxet wodahS sa dezzub enohp ym ,emoh evord ew sA
.deppans I ”!ni gnikaerb ton er’eW“
*** .egnever rof osla tub
”-segnahc ydob ruoy ega uoy sa tub“
”,siht ekil ll’uoy ,yawynA ?haey hO“
,htrof dna kcab gnitnirps erew wodahS dna eulB ,epipniard eht nwod kcab dils I nehW
,wodniw eht tuo kcab eye ym tsac I
.seye ym dellor I
.dnuora gnifoog pots ot elba demees reven yehT
,pu em dekcip rehtoM-neD nehW
.deknilb eh revenehw seye sih ssorca eparcs ot demees dna
.skeew ni ereh morf tuo dehsulf stnecs eht fo enon
,rethgual rieht ni sevlow ekil gnilwoh
.wodniw eht hguorht ni flesym llup dna pu hcaer ot evah tsuj d’I neht dna
,meht dniheb ylthgit pu sliat rieht delruc yeht sa gnihctaw ,meht deksa I
,moor eht tuohguorht esor ti fo tnecs ehT
”,ydaerla ereh morf tuo mih llems nac I“ .deggag eulB
.hgiht eht no wodahS gnikcams ,deilper eulB ”,gnithgif eb ot su rof emit eht tog ton s’liat-thgiartS
.erutuf thgirb a tnaw uoy fi yteicos flow gnoma yaw ruoy ekam ot woh nrael ot tog ev’uoY“
.enoyna neeb evah dluoc eh ,tnecs sih rebmemer t’ndid I fi taht emas dna kcots os serutaef hsiflow
.krims sih edih ot niav ni deirt wodahS
.meht dniheb pu delruc sliat
toof s’eulB no nwod pmats wodahS gnihctac ,gnihton dias I
,yoj rof elims tsuj t’ndid tI
.gniht ’ruf deyd tog ev’uoy fi flow a eb uoy nac woh‘
eht ton ;niaga siht toN
.hcrot a ekil walf taht ot dleh I dna
.ti deniur dna htuom reh denepo ehs erofeb
lufesu gniht eno syas tooc dlo eht raews I ,zeeG“         ”.eman
,sgel ym gnipmup ,meht denioj I
,sdrawpu del epipniard euqitna ,ytsur a ,hcrop eht fo edis eht ot tsuJ
.gniklus llits ,detroter wodahS ”,eno ekil sevaheb eh hcum woh gniredisnoc ,esuoh a
.etalocohc fo lluf selzzum ruo gniffuts sdehs ekib eht dniheb
.swap rieht htiw sevlesmeht ta detterf sevlow regnuoy eht sa gnihgual
.hguone suoivbo saw ecnedive eht
,neht dnuora llits saw tsael ta ohw ,rehtaf-neD dnA
;gninetsil ton s’eivE suoivbo s’tI
;evisnefed ,deye-nellus ,revo dehcnuh saw eH
.enam delgnat reh hguorht swalc reh gnibmoc
.ruf gninniht s’loof dlo taht htaenrednu morf tuo dereep yeht sa
,rehtegot doots ohw seiksuh owt eht ta nwod gnikool
,rebmemer dluohs uoY“
knarp tcefrep eht tog ev’ew os - emit eht lla ereht ni neh emag a ekil pu uoy pooc yeht lufwa s’ti ,haeY“
.spil reh ta gnihctiwt nirg eht kcab dloh ot tseb sih gniod ,delworg ehs
,setunim net detiaw I
,sned rehto htiw tuo nehw flesym evaheb ot woh wonk t’ndid ylraelc I reh ot
.tnemeticxe rieht tnev ot gniyrt
,erows eulB ”!liaT-thgiartS ylno s’ti ,kcuF“
”?gniod er’ew tahw yltcaxe s’taht tuB“
.edis rehtie no emas eht saw gnihtyreve
,nopu dezies I taht gniht eht saw pils tahT
,cirtcele tub eltbus
,ti htiw dna - roolf eht no gnirettalc riahc sih ,kcab tpael moT
;tnap dna elzzum ym edistuo eugnot ym llol ot em gnicrof
.edisni deppils dna
.gniralf slirtson
.nus eht ni enam kciht reh gnikahs
.tniop a evorp ot fi sa stekcop dellif repparw reh ni dnuora gnigammur swap
.epipniard eht fo dloh koot I sa wap reh htiw ssarg eht gnikcik
.ekatsim s’wodahS gnitcerroc
.selur namuh evah ot taerg s’ti yas stnerap ruoy tahw etipsed ,liaT-thgiartS eeS“
”,yaw taht pu teg nac uoy yaw oN“
.esion gniooc kcom a gnikam dna skeehc s’yksuh eht gnibbarg
,delwoh eh ”!gnikram-tnecs fo snoitacilppa dna ecnatropmi eht no troper egap evif a tnaw I yadnuS txen ,rebmemeR“
.deeh ekat em ekam ot elba neeb evah thgim eh
.hsibbur lla s’ti ,moM“
.naelc sroolf eht gnibburcs eno eht eb d’I esle
,deveileb ehs ,taht sgniht erew yehT
;erutuf s’rettil reh tuoba liat reh gniltsirb syawla saw ehS
,dennirg ehs ”,gnihton od t’nac yeht
”!oga gnol ti deknoc evah d’I neht ,esac eht t’nsaw ti fI“
”!liat ruoy dloh uoy woh ton s’taht ,riS“
.ytinummoc detfilpu eht fo sredael eht era sevlow eW“
.yaweerf eht otno devrews dna no srotacidni eht deppilf ehs sa snoitseuq fo lluf saw rehtom-neD
,deunitnoc eh ”,duorp egatireh ruoy od lliw uoy dna
,em dniheb dehcaer dna walc ym htiw nepo pac eht deppop I
.llew ega ot dnet t’nod eW“
.drawrof nael dna tniop ot srae s’moor eht gnicrof ,derumrum eh
,gnikool em thguac yeht sa noos sA
.htnom a ecno wenk I tnecs a dna
.eussit detnecs-redneval a htiw ruf ym morf rebbols sih dehsurb I elihw nmutua ni hcnarb sselfael a ekil hgih liat gninniht sih gnidloh ,selsia eht nwod gnitturts ot kcab gniog ,yawa dellup eH
- alumrof laiceps htiw ffo ti hsaw ot tog ev’uoy
- ecaf s’wodahS ta depiws ehs sa gnisruc ,mih ta kcab deppans dna delworg eulB
.ruf on tog ev’yeht esuaceb meht erongi t’ndluohs uoy ,wonk uoy tuB“
- deliaf dna - deirt eh sa
.secart eht fo eerf teg ot gnithgif sgod-dels ekil rehto hcae htiw tuoba depparcs yeht
.gnitatirri dna duol saw ti ,no oidar eht htiw nevE
.liat reh gnihctulc ,tuo deirc retsis s’eivetS ,eivE
”,regae naht erom m’I ,yadot retfA“
”.senob ym otni peerc ot detrats dloc eht sa noos sa tnuh eht ni dne ym tem evah dluow I ,syad dlo eht nI
,dehgis ehs ”,ydaer rennid teg neht dna yresrun morf setam-rettil regnuoy ruoy pu kcip ot tog ev’I“         .fo
tnemtimmoc sih rof tcepser eud mih wohs ll’uoy epoh I
,oddik swap tog ev’uoY“ .deggurhs eulB
,ksed eht nopu smra tnuag sih gnitser
,dik su dna uoy
.htuoy emoselbuort eht no selcitra repapswen tsetal eht morf kni htiw deniats yllauteprep swap
,ecaf ym ssorca hcterts nirg a dehctaw I rorrim eht nI .og tel neht
.pu yaw ym dellup I sa eulB ta dekrims I
,enod siht teg ew fI“ .denevretni eulB
”?nrael uoy did tahW ?hcnul gib a tae uoy diD
;tluser a sa yadnuS eerf a decneirepxe reven I
rieht draehrevo d’I
;mrif dleh ti tub ,delbbow swercs ehT
.’yerp sti sklats flow eurt a
,issaveleT yb ”erutlruC retnuoC“
.sreltna ytfol htiw
”?kcis teg I fi tahW
”!yawyna ti tuohtiw etalocohc lla ekam yeht
”?eh si ,palf-god a evah dna laref a peek ot eno ton s’eh dna ,dekcol s’rooD“
,duol erew sraC
!ports t’nod ,no emoc wA“         .derettum eh
,pil sih tib dna delbmurg wodahS
,daeha no decar I
.sevlow eht hguorht delppir tnemeticxe fo noitanimur A .deppord nip eht
.deveiler s’mom ym ,yas attoG“
.seiksuh ysion ,duol esoht
,flow a edam tahw fo dradnats eht tes dah ohw flow elbarenev ,dlo tahT
.liat delruc sih gnilaever
”,keew tsal uoy tes I syasse ruoy tuo teg esaelp ,woN“ .dias eh
.egde no tac a fo sriah eht ekil yawa gnidneb ylnrobbuts sdnoces
- hguoht meht dehs reven eh tnaem sciteneg siH
.tuo gnuh ew emit tsal dedda dah eulB sthgilhgih dnolb eht etipsed ni gnidnelb tlep yhtrae
,sevlow ekil dekool regnol on ssalc ehT
.thgiarts deniamer ,lla ti fo etips ni hcihw - liat ym gnittap ylsuoituac ,kcab dehcaer ehS
.swalc gnikcalc htiw rood eht hguorht gnihsur ruf fo edit eht yb edisa tpews
.kcapkcab ym ni leg riah fo top eht tuoba gnikniht tpek I
.syad eseht hsilgnE ylno kaeps su fo ynam oot esuaceb tra gniyd a s’ti yltnerappA
.liat ym ni gnilgnit wollof ot tcnitsni eht
.knuht knuht ,knuht knuht ,knuht knuhT  .sbals etercnoc s’daor eht neewteb spag eht revo evord ew emit yreve gnihctiwt morf
”,pu evig dna nwod eil ot tirips ruo tsniaga s’ti tuB“
,yrrow fo dekeer eh
’?liat ruoy fo tuo leg eht hsaw ot gniog er’uoy kniht uoy od
,staoc yffulf rieht ot gnignilc gnat dirca eht llems dluoc I
.rorroh kcom ni meht gnillup
liat ym fo dloh mrif a peek ot elbanu ,rewohs eht ot pu dehsur I dessimsid tog yllanif I nehW
.lehctas sih ni dnuora gnigammur ,dehgual wodahS
”.ylsuoires uoy ekat lliw eno on ,yltcerroc liat ruoy gnidloh tuohtiw weivretni na ot pu nrut uoy fI
”,flow dlo na gnieb drah s’tI“
,sevlow tuoba wonk dluohs uoy gniht tsrif eht esuaceB
,detneler eh ”,tniop a evah od uoY“
,semaJ otni depmub ew nehw sselecirp saw ecaf reh no kool ehT
***   ”.erif no esuoh a naht nuf erom eb annog si siht ,liaT-thgiartS hO“
”!em evol yeht esuaceb em ot ti evig stnerap ym ,yeH“
”,htiw pu tup ot dah ev’I parc ’flow eurt‘ siht lla rof thgir mih sevreS“
.dneirf sih ta gnihgual dna gnirekcins ,yawa depmuj eh tub
.ysae efil dah sgoD .meht deivne I
,rekcib ot meht gnivaeL
,daeh ym evoba smra ym gnidloh ,sehsub eht fo tuo tsrub I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.flow gniraef-noom a saw rehtom-neD   issaveleT yb
.em sdrawot gnir a gniwolb
skram-hctarcs fo elpuoc a ni derevoc raj revlis a em gniworht
,derepsihw htob yeht
”!lli taht si eh fi neve
.sgod tuoba parc taht lla gniweps
.eman naht rehtar tnecs yb ezirogetac dluohs uoy yhw dna ,liat ruoy dloh ot woh tuoba ffuts erom tsuJ
,dehgis wodahS ”,eno prahs a s’liaT-thgiartS
”!thgir s’liaT-thgiartS ,pu tuhS“
.tniop eht dessim yehT
,gnilwoh nmad sih lla htiw pu enoyreve gnikaw deppots eh emit tuobA
;ees ot nialp saw tI
”,semufrep htiw erutan sih naemed t’nseod flow eurt a
.tliub tnemeticxe sa gnihctiwt srae ym
.gniggas sredluohs ,dezigolopa ehs ”,evaheb ot woh wenk uoy dias uoy nehw uoy detsurt evah dluohs I“
,ruf ym otni ti gnibbur
***   .eciton ot eson eht dah syad eseht enoyna taht ton
.llits doots drofloW
,sehsub eht otni knuls I
,dnah ruoy ni til ti hctac t’nod yeht fI“ .gnihgual
”!rehtegot sned gnidliub ni tseretni on evah neve yehT
,detuohs dna dehgual yehT
,oga snoitareneg seneg ruo morf tuo delzzif t’ndah ti fI
,meht was ehs nehw deppilf rehtoM-neD
”!erutuf eht tuoba kniht ot daerd I
,hteet ym dnuorg I
,ti fo dir tnaw uoy fi
,kcab rehto hcae dehsup yeht
.emoc yeht sa ynniks sa saw eulB hguoht neve
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.sdrawpu ti gnillup
,kcab tas wodahS ”,tniop riaF“
.tius swollof esle enoyreve
- su htiw tuo gnah uoy taht taerg ytterp s’ti kniht eW“
.sehcnarb eht ni thguac ’sreltna‘ ym sa tuoba meht gnihsarht
.syebo god A .god on era uoy
,em guh ot revo tpael ehs sa htuom reh fo tuo gnillol eugnot ,delims eulB
,taht ta yltnelis deddon
enam nworb esiwrehto reh ni skaerts elprup dedaf htiw flow gnuoy a gnirutcel
;elzzum ym delknirw I
,deunitnoc ehs ”,aedi taerg a tog s’wodahS tuB“
.derepsihw eh ”,sgod htiw ezinretarf reven dluohs uoy
.elbatciderp woh - sdehs ekib eht dniheb gnikomS
”,ti htiw uoy thguac yeht fi detacsifnoc teg ylbaborp d’ti esiwrehto ffo gnidnarb eht ekat ot dah ew ,lleW“
,liat deggar sih otni leg kciht eht gnikrow
;rehcaet daeh eht nosremE yb moorssalc eht otni dellarroc sevlesruo dnuof sevlow eht lla yad txen ehT
.ydemer eht gniniatnoc but eulb llams eht em gnissot
,dedda eulB ”?sevig tahw ,haeY“
”?ereht ni teg ot gniog uoy er’woh oS“
tsniaga no srotacidni eht dekcilc rehtom-neD