.kniht uoy sa dab sa t’nsi tI“
.ti raeh ot dnuora saw eh elihw t’ndah yeht ,tsael ta rO
,orevO ovitlA yb
,tsud eht ni nwod dial eh
esirprus ni deffuh raeB
”?llew rehto hcae gnitaert dna gnirahs tuoba uoy fo lla llet I did tahw dnA
”.ecivres taht rof egnahcxe riaf a eriuqer lliw I tuB .sey ,noitcurtsni emos reffo ot elba eb thgim I“
,tsaerb dna sgniw sih revo sregnif reh dehsurb ehs sA
thgilf koot nevaR ”.won ylF
.meht ot ekops ehs
”.nevaR htiw romuh fo esnes ym erahs ot gnilliw m'I dnA“ .etoyoC dias
.gnitiaw ,mih dedrager ehS
,hguoht ,elihw a retfA
”,yppup ,gnorw ton si hsilooF“
.seert eht otni ffo gniylf erofeb sknaht sih debbob dna
uoy ot doog dnuos lliw ti tub
.decnuonna ehs ”,tsrif xoF“
.dlihc ,pu ekaW“ dias tI
sessarg eht gnoma flesreh dial dna ,gnas ehs
.thgilnus eht ni der gnimalf taoc hsul sih
.gnis ot nrael ot hsiw I“
,ysub saw enoyrevE
”,pan gnol a rof emiT“
.senihw dna skrab wef a saw eganam dluoc eh lla
.ecnahc eno ylno evah lliw uoy esuaceb
.mih dlot xof eht ”,erahs ot reffo t’ndeen uoY“
.ylduol dekculc nerW sutcaC
,kciuq dna yraw eb tsum netae ehT
.taht did dna ,thguoht eh
.meht otni thgir gnikool dna
,elohw laem sih nwod deflow etoyoC
.uoy evag eh tahw rof nruter ni
,ylesraoh ylno gnas xof eht wenk eH
”.ees I ,mih raeh uoY“ .dekniw xoF
ylwols daeh sih desiar etoyoC
,truh tlef tsuj eh tsrif tA .detcejed dna
,tsafkaerb emos dnif ot gnitiaw neve tuohtiW
.od nac I tseb eht ,snossel uoy evig lliw I“
.deddon xoF .deksa eh
.peelsa yletaidemmi saw dna dnuorg eht no nwod flesmih dial eh
,yadot neve si ti sa hcum saw eciov gnikaeps sih rof ,dekaorc eh ”,hA“
”,em morf tfig ruoy elots xoF“
”.em fo hsiloof yreV .hsiloof saw ti tub ,esnes yna ni gnorw neeb evah ton yam tahT
orevO ovitlA ecalperiF ehT fO dneirF yb ”ecioV s’etoyoC“
.gnirps eht ni mih ot ti nruter dna neht ti raew em tel dluow eh spahrep os ,retniw ni ti raew ot mih edabrof aiaG
nerdlihc reh eb ot serutaerc eht edam ehs
,uoy ot ti tnarg ot rewop ym ni si ti fI
.enog saw ehs dna
.aiaG ta thgiarts dekool dna seye sih htob denepo xoF
skcor owt neewteB
daeh sih koohs eh dna
”.kcalb niamer ot evresed I .tsev eht peek mih teL
.hguoht ,eciov ruoy egnahc ot cigam on evah I
.mih dniheb deggaw liat sih sa neve dnuorg eht ot sgelerof sih gnirewol ,aiaG ot dewob etoyoC
.lluf saw traeh sih tub
.srae eht neewteb daeh sih dekorts dna
”.edih ot yrt ton oD
”.uoy revo taolg ot tnaw lliw dna em rof gnikool eb ll’eh
.rehcaet a rof sdrib eht gnoma ksa ot flesmih desimorp eh tpels eh erofeB
”?flesruoy rof yas ot evah uoy od tahW
,senot mrif ni decnuonna ydaL eht ”,ees I“
,rof deksa uoy taht tfig doog a saw tI
,meht dehctaw aiaG
,sdrib eht fo tsom ekil dna
,ezag s'drib eht dewollof etoyoC
,niaga sdnah reh otni erutaerc laudividni hcae gnikat dna ,aedi na dah ehs tsal tA
.nus gnittes eht fo nosmirc eht sa thgirb sa tsomla
.relpmis si tseuqer yM
.deneppah tsuj dah tahw ta lla ta hgual t’ndluoc eh esuaceb enog saw ti llet dluoc eh dna
edam ehs ezeerb eht ni derettulf yeht taht os
snoitaerc reh evorpmi tseb ot woh derednop dna tas aiaG
.uoy rof sepoh retteb dah I“
.denetsil dna elihw a tas yehT
.dias eh ”,em htiw klaW“
mih gnitnuat nevaR fo demaerd eh nehw nwad erofeb tsuj litnu llew tpels etoyoc eht ,deriT
?etoyoC morf laets uoy did tahw tuB
.knab eht gnola dnas eht ni gniworg smulp ruos htiw
.doof dnif ot gid ro stsen nepo raet dna
.ylsuoicipsus deksa nevar eht
.eralg eht tsniaga seye sih desolc dna
,taews ot elba neeb dah rehtie fI
,semit lareves deirt eH
.sedis lla morf dekool eh woh etoyoC gniwohs
.aiaG ot laeppa tseb dah uoy kniht I
.elbide tub ruos era smulp eht dna
.noitaler yksud sih ta dereep dna
.tnemssarrabme ni rednu liat sih dekcut tub ,deyebo
traeh sih ni peed egru na tlef etoyoC
.tuo tes yeht erofeb niaga dehcterts dna doots etoyoC
.deksa nerw eht ”?uoy pleh eh diD
”,ffo liat ym tib nevaR“
.ylimaf ym era uoy ,nerdlihc devoleB“
,wor nopu wor ,reh dnuora tas srellewd htrae dna ria eht fo lla nehW
.tnessa reh deddon ehs yllaniF
”.emit eht lla suoires eb tonnac enoyrevE
”,ylthgit erom desolc htuom ym peek ot deen I spahreP“
.uoy mrah ot ton esimorp I
,tsal emac etoyoC
.yad wen eht teerg ot gninrom ta gnas eh
.uoy ot repsihw nac I erehw dnats dna neht nwod emoC“
,retniw ni neve hcum egnahc ton dluow
.detaehc neeb dah eh taht ezilaer ot etoyoC rof gnol ekat t’ndid ti tub
.elzzum sih htiw sniatnuom eht ta detniop xof eht ,niaga gnisiR
.dennirg xoF eht siht tA
.gnimoc saw retniw wenk yeht ,looc ot nageb sthgin eht nehw dna
.gnis ot detnaw llits eH .dehca traeh sih
.niagrab ruo ot ssentiw eb lliw ereh xoF“ ”.enola
yldlob pu deppets nevaR nehw ,noonretfa eht ni ,yad tsal eht no saw tI
.ytinav ruoy dna eciov ruoy si tsol evah uoy llA
,ovitlA rednu onimA yrruF dna ,lysaeW
.desolc seye sih tpek etoyoC
.taht ta derednow etoyoC
,gnignis s'nerw eht yb desserpmi yrev ton saw etoyoC
.llits uoy evol I
.kcor gniretlehs eht dnuora dekeep dna pu tas etoyoC
.ti yfitnedi ot tnemom a mih koot ti dna shtnom ynam rof nwonk ton dah eh tnecs a htiw delkcirp eson siH
.era uoy erehT“
.erised sih reh llet ot tsirw s’aiaG no tas dna
,tsew eht ni tes nus eht sa tsuj tresed eht fo egde eht gnihcaeR
,snif dna selacs werg hsif ehT
seye sih deworran xoF ehT
”?ruf ruoy ot enod uoy evah tahW“ ,deksa eh ”,nisuoC“
.feiht nwonk a era uoy taht yfingis ot etihw eb won lliw ti fo pit eht tub ,kcab liat ruoy evah llahs uoY
”.laed fo dnik yna otni mih klat ot elba neeb t'nevah I tub
.stfig rieht dna mrof rieht deviecer won dah slamina dna sdrib eht llA
enola etoyoc eht gnivael
nevaR htob taht dezilaer eh
”.syad tsrif esoht ni ecivda ym ot netsil ton did nerdlihc ym fo emos tahT“
.niar retniw a ni yrd mih peek dna mih mraw tey
.teef sih revo liat nworb yffulf sih gnipparw
.seveiht era uoy fo htoB
.ti nrael ot woh erus t’nsaw eh tub
”?emoh sih ot yaw eht taht sI
.eye eno ylno denepo xoF
gnirps gnilkcirt a revo dehcrep eno kcalb eht dnuof
.woleb sdinac owt eht ta nwod dereep dna gnos sih dedne nevar eht tsal tA
.erofeb saw I naht gnikool retteb on m’I liat a flah ylno htiw tub ,yhsalf si ruf deR
.rehtie ,etoyoC ees ot deticxe yrev t'nsaw nerw eht demees tI
”ecioV s’etoyoC“ saw sihT
”.hgual srehto ekam dna ,hgual ,skcirt yalp osla nac I taht os terces s’aiaG em wohS
.mih eripsni t’ndid yalpsid eht dna sduolc htiw deliev saw ti tub
.nisuoc derruf-nworb sih fo sesoprup eht devres ti tub
.dehctaw etoyoC sa eugnot sih htiw flesmih demoorg dna
.snialp yrd eht ot ffo nar dna
.rettiwt dna prihc fo surohc a ot nwad ta ekowa etoyoC
.meht fo hcae htiw emit erom koot ehs dna
.dnuos suoicipsus yna ta ro thgil tsrif eht ta ekawa eb dluow eh dna
.worbeye na desiar xoF .derewol srae
kcalb erew srehtaef siH
,etoyoC ot emac ehs tsal ta nehW
,seye sih denepo etoyoC
.yawyna mih dehcaorppa tub
,retaw gniwolf fo maerts a ot mih thguorb xof ehT
.daeh reh gnikahs ,mih dlot ehs ”,emit lla hguorht nerdlihc ruoy dna ,eb llahs dna era uoy draugkcalB“ .hsinav dna
”.gnis nevaR raeh dna og lliw I
.daetsni ytpme leef I
,erutan dna dnik ruoy ot gnidrocca stfig deviecer hcae evah uoY“
,llew sa revieced a dna feiht a uoy llac syawla lliw emoS
,denrael eb ot dah ti ebyaM
”.lla ta mih ees ton did I
,niap ni depley xoF
?nevaR eht morf gnikees eb xoF dluoc tahW
,ria eht otni welf dna yrc tnahpmuirt a evag nevaR ,os did eh sA
.thgilf nekat ydaerla dah drib eht
,yb esolc etiuq s'eh ,seY ?oot uoY“
,edis tfel sih no knis dna nedder ot nageb nus eht sA
”?nevaR htiw gnihtemos edart ot gniyrt erew uoY“
.desufer I tub ,eno riaf a neeb evah dluow tI“
,egas tnargarf a yb neddih yltrap
,ssenrevelc hcum oot uoy gnivig fo ytliug ma I tub
,noos dna ,semoh gnikam
.tiw fo tfig ym fo erahs a rof nruter ni em hcaet ot deerga eh dna mih dnuof I“
,esnes s’retskcirt ym fo noitrop egral a mih evag ylurt I“
em ot emoc lliw uoy ,eno yb enO
gnirewoc erew htob taht dezilaer eh nehw desirprus erom neve saw eH
,gnittes saw nus ehT .dehgis dna
”.hguone llew eraf lliw ylimaf ruoy dna uoy dna
sa egap rohtua moc.sdaerdooG sih no dna
mih drawot denael ehS
,meht ssorca dehtaerb dna seye reh denepo ehs ,yllaniF
.gnos ot noitanilcni yna nwohs dah slamina yrruf eht fo enon tub
,neht ylkciuq emoC
,yawa welf dna yks eht otni esor drib eht ,tlusni taht htiw dnA
.tsal ta seye s’ydaL eht otni pu dekool nevaR
.hguoht ,nerW sutcaC tsuj saw tI
.em htiw roloc der sih erahs thgim eh thguoht I“
.elttil a ekahs htrae eht tlef etoyoC
.evah emos ,tcaf nI“ .dias ehs
,gnilbmert dna tnelis doots nevaR
,stfig dna mrof lanigiro sih mih nevig dah ehs nehw sA
.emoh drawot swap nwo sih gninrut erofeb
.os ti esusim dluow uoy thguoht reven I dna
.noziroh nrehtron eht tsniaga skaep fo enil eulb eht ta kaeb sih detniop dna ,deddon nerw ehT
.etoyoc eht dehctaw dna tas nevaR ,delffurnU
”?drib kcalb ,flesruoy rof yas ot evah uoy od tahW“
,yrots elohw eht dlot dna
.uoy dehcuot sah tnecs rieht dna slerdnuocs owt htiw sredluohs debbur evah uoY
,desimorp dah ehs sa tsuj dewener saw ti dna
.edam neeb dah telracs fo tsev elbavomer s’nevaR yaw eht
.flesreh ot deddon dna tfel stnacilppus rehto on erew ereht taht was ehS
.hguone ylisae gnola epol dluoc eh owt ro elim a retfa tub
thgirb erew seye sih tub
esor xoF ,rits etoyoC gnieeS
”.em dewohs aiaG tahw uoy wohs lliw I nehT
hcae ot denetsil dah ehs erofeb sthgin dna syad ynam koot tI
.ecalp gnidih eht no kcehc ot enoG“ .deddon xof ehT
.woble ro eenk ot swap eht morf ylno tub ,erofeb sa nworb krad erew sgel siH
deedni si taht dna
piy llirhs a htiw ria eht otni gnarps eh nehT
.nisuoc ,emoh yaw ruoy no ylefas levarT
.yllacisum gnis ot nrael thgim eh woh kniht ot deirt etoyoC
nevaR drawot denael etoyoc eht ,nrut sih nI
.kaeb sih morf gnignah liat suoiruxul s’xoF fo flah htiw
,elcric a ni decnad dna doots xof ehT
si yrots s’yadot dna
.meht otni efil gnihtaerb erofeb
.mih pleh ot esufer si od thgim aiaG tsrow eht taht dediced eh dne eht ni tub
.taht naht ylriaf erom uoy taert tsum eh taht swonk nevaR nevE“
.daeh sih gnikahs ,delworg etoyoC
nerdlihc s’nerdlihc ruoy dna nerdlihc ruoy dna uoY
”,ylesiw romuh fo esnes
”.erus rof s’taht ,gnirps emoc kcab tsev sih gnitteg eb t’now nevaR
?nevaR dnif uoy diD“
”?gnis ot em hcaet uoy naC“
.raef I ,gnihtyreve fo thgil ekam ot ytiliba ym I roN“
,mih ot denrut etoyoC nehw lavorppa deddon xoF
.emahs ni seye sih derevoc dna
.thgil flah eht otni dereep dna
,repmihw elttil das a htiW
ylfeirb seye reh desolc ehs
.xoF ot dnah a tuo dleh ehS
.tneserp regnol on erew taht sgniht neve dna
,dnuora selim rof gnihtyreve yfitnedi mih tel taht
”.tiw tsol sih rof esnepmocer ni etoyoC ot mih evag I tfig eht fo trap drawa I ,tnemyap ni tuB
llems fo esnes gnizama na deviecer xoF taht saw ti oS
,tresed eht rof edaM
,thgil fo remmihs A
.delooc ti sa ria eht otni tsud deppihw sdniw gnorts tub raelc ylralucitrap saw yad taht yks eht ,deneppah ti sA
mih drawot denael aiaG
.tes nus eht hctaw ot
,syad ruoy fo dne eht oT“
,em ot tfig enif reh fo flah yawa evag I ?gnorw gnihtoN“
.spit kcalb htiw der nosmirc ot denrut srehtaef eht
”.nac uoy sa ti htiw llew sa oD .erom dna
,der ot egnaro ot wolley morf gninrut yks eht gnihctaW .tnecifingam saw
yldnof delims ehS
.etihw dna kcalb ni ees ylno uoy fi sroloc ynam fo esroh a si ohw
.deraeppasid dna dnuorg eht otni dedaf ehs ezeerb eltneg a fo yteltbus eht htiW
.hcaer sih evoba tsuj gnilkcuhc dna
.dias eh ”,ruoh siht ta su raen etiuq eb dluohs nevaR“
,hguoht ,sniatnuom eht ees regnol on dluoc eh nehW
sredluohs s’xof eht revo ruf der eht ta gut ot nageb eh erofeb ”!feihT !feihT“ gnimaercs
,oga gnol os reve ,emit fo nwad eht nI
,kcor eht morf sdray wef a nwod tas eH
.nevar eht ot elzzum sih desiar etoyoC
.rednop ot emit dah eh dna
,uoy knaht a sa sregnif s’rehtom eht tsniaga eugnot knip sih hsurb ot derad xoF
”.hgual lliw enoyreve ton dna
mih ta deknilb ehS
.tsehc sih morf traeh yrev sih ward ot denetaerht
.tpmetnoc sih wohs ot sesion gnizzub edam dna
,deirt dna htaerb werd eH
swodahs dna sroloc gnitfihs eht erimda ot nwod tas etoyoC
?etairporppa si kniht uoy od tnemegduj tahW
,rehtona eno no skcab ruoy nrut uoy erofeb ylluferac knihT
.tfel dah nerW sutcaC tub ,swap sih htaeneb morf dekeep etoyoC
,tfeht dna yvne fo ytliug era uoY“
.reh erofeb gniknilb doots xoF dna
.taht rof eraperp ot enod eb ot dah erom nevE
,spahrep sdrib eht sa yllacisum sa toN“
.deirc eh ”,gnitnuh ton ma I“
,ssarg eht no nwod tas aiaG rehtoM nehT
,mih dlot ehs ”,ereht ,hA“
”.tceles uoy tfig eht htiw
,siht od ot desimorp nevaR
,htrae fo serutaerc ehT
.gnis ot em pleh ylno lliw uoy fi
,kcor sih fo pot eht ot pu kcab welf neht
,rehguor emaceb dnuorg eht fo epols ehT
reverof evil llahs
ecno sgniw sih deppalf drib eht dna ,dnah thgir reh tuo dleh ehS
)rettiwT no ovitlA@ tsuj(
”.rehtie tnemhsinup epacse ot tcepxe t’nod dnA
gnol erofeb dna srae rieht dewollof etoyoC dna xoF
.deednI“ .dekaorc eh
,yad eht fo hcum roF
.thgin gnihcaorppa eht fo ssenlooc gnipeerc eht yojne dna
seert bmilc mih tel ot gnorts dna gnol werg swalc sih sa
.oot sretsis dna srehtorb lla era uoy snaem tahT
detevoc uoy sroloc eht dna
.mih gnihctaw dna
.od llahs I os dna
”.hguone doog ton saw eciov ym esuaceb em hcaet t’ndluoc eh dias eh
,flah dna flah ,uoy htiw ti erahs ot gnilliw m’I
,daehrevo gniylf sevod eht draeh eh
ruoy esU“ .eciwt dezeens dna
,wodaem a no ro tresed eht ni saw eh rehtehw
.swap sih htiw ecaf sih derevoc dna
.nerdlihc s’nerdlihc ruoy dna ,nerdlihc ruoy dna ,od llahs uoy os dna ,kcalb niamer ot evresed uoy ,yas uoy sA .gnihton
?tresed eht ni ereh gniod eb xoF dluow tahW !xoF
.llew sa nworb krad deniamer eson dna srae sih fo spit eht dna
”.su fo rehtie did ti doog elttil tub ,uoy rof nevar eht dnuof I
.thgin eht rof ecalp gnitser a thguos eh
,degnahcnu erew ruf ylleb dna ffur tsehc etihw siH
etoyoC ”.em ot emoc ,etoyoC yhS“
.hceeps reh deunitnoc aiaG
”.flesmih etam a sdeen eh nehw ,gnirps eht ni nevaR ot kcab tsev der eht evig d'I
”?taht htiw yawa teg ot tcepxe uoy od woH“
.tcidrev reh deredner ehs erofeb os enod evah dluow ylerus yeht
.nageb eh ”,nisuoc ,gninrom dooG“
,dehsinav nus eht erofeb tsuj deralf selprup dna sder eht nehW
.dehcatta snoitidnoc htiw
.gnas dna mih dekorts ehs yllautnevE
,sniatnuom eht fo sllihtoof eht ni gnidnats erew yeht taht dezilaer etoyoC ,deedni dnA
.dnif dluoc eh retaw tahw fo egatnavda koot dna
.dneirf ym ,thgir era uoy spahreP“ .deddon dna
,liat deniur sih ta kcab gnikooL
”.gnihton em hcaet dluoc eh em dlot eh neht dna
.mih depacse taht dnuos ylno eht saw enihw lufnruom a emit sihT
,htuos eht ot levart s’yad a fo trap tseb eht saw tI
.dias ehs lla saw
,daeh s’etoyoC revo gnilcriC
,reh erofeb tas eH
.desimorp ehs ”,won noom dna nus eht ot gnis ot elba eb lliw uoY“
”,regnis taerg on ma I“
.srats eht nword dna
sgniw sih daerps nevar eht
emoh nesohc sih fo etamilc tresed hsrah ehT
.eciov gnignis a dnif t’ndluoc tsuj tub
”.ti noitseuq ehs dluohs aiaG erofeb ssentiw taht raeb lliw I dnA“
”,mih htiw niagrab ot hsiw I sa
.rof reh deksa dah I taht eno eht
,tib a srehtaef sih delffur nevaR
yks eht daerpsrevo ot nageb thgil sa meht denepo eh dna
,detaert era uoy yldab woh ro leef uoy ylwol woh rettam on taht rebmemeR
,mih ot tfig eht derrefsnart I retfA
.gnos gnizzub sih ni desuap drib eht
,detacilpmoc tsom erew htrae eht fo serutaerc yrruf ehT
gnineve ta nus eht ronoh ot elba eb ot ekil dluow I tub
.ffur sih dekorts dna
mih fo tnorf ni gnittauqs aiaG dnuof dna
,der suortsul a saw taoc sih fo tser ehT
.hsiw tsetaerg ruoy em llet dna
.ylluferac tuo kcab ot dah eH
”,egnarts tib a smees tI“
.pu evig ton did etoyoC
.srebmun rieht gniylpitlum
,nerdlihc rehto ym naht uoy tuoba stiw erom evah llits uoy ,os nevE
.edih rehtar dluow uoy nehw pu uoy wohs lliw
,weiv otni ylduorp detturts xoF
teef eros htiw emoh drawot denrut eH
,kaeb sih ni ti debbarg dna liat eht ta welf eH
peelS .dekrep srae sih tpek tub pan a rof delttes eh
.noitcerid sih tpek eh os
,niaga gnas dna semit eerht sdnah reh deppalc aiaG
.gninruter saw xoF taht mih denraw eson sih
,nevar eht dnif ot niaga seye sih desiar eh nehW
”.taht htiw uoy pleh ot od nac I gnihton si erehT .sselepoh s’tahT“
.hguoht ,tseuq sih ni dedaussid eb ot tuoba ton saw etoyoC
.gnirewsna erofeb elihw a rof meht fo htob ta derats nevaR
.nevaR eht ot og dluohs uoY“ .dezzub drib eht
.drah nwod gnitib
dniw eht ekil nur dluoc taht teef tog tibbaR
”?on ,tsafkaerb fo deen ni eb tsum uoy dnA
,ecalp koot siht sA
etoyoC ot eciov gnignis ruoy tnarg I
gnipporctuo ykcor a no tas eh
.yllufthguoht mih ta derats aiaG
.tsrif ta erew uoy sa kcalb raeppa dna yawa meht tup tsum uoy nmutua yB
?mih edart uoy lliw tahW“
.devomnu deraeppa ,revewoh ,xoF
,wob lamrof a edam etoyoC
.niaga deednI“ .denihw eh
dne eht ta ffulf etihw tnaillirb a htiw
.uoy ot evig ot gniht erom eno evah I tub
,rehto hcae llik neve dna lerrauq semitemos lliw uoy taht os uoy edam evah I wonk I
htron yawa welf dna
,dessessop snisuoc degniw sih fo ynam naht reprahs dnim a detacidni seye thgirb siH
,deknilb drib ehT
.ecno sdnah reh deppalc dna pu doots ydaL eht ,taht htiW
.was eh tahw eveileb t’ndluoc eH
.gnos drib tniaf a fo dnuos eht ta dekrep srae siH
”.ereh fo htron sniatnuom eht ni gnineve hcae sgnis eH
.sdaeh rieht revo ria eht morf keirhs yrgna na draeh yeht
,nevaR gnikees emoc I“
.enituor yliad a poleved ot nageb dlrow eht dna yb delf syad remmus ehT
.netae eht dna sretae era erehT
,laog rieht ot yaw eht flah naht erom on tub ,emit doog gnikam eb ot demees yeht tsrif tA
?nevaR morf laets uoy did tahw tuB
.dednammoc aiaG ”,won nevaR“
.dias eh ”,tnemeerga siht ssentiw I“ .deddon xoF
”?sniatnuom eht ot uoy sgnirb tahW
”.gnihtemos did yllaer uoY
.drawrof pets a koot dna
.nrut sih dah xoF ,yllautnevE
”.sehcnarb nerrab eht dna
,pal s’aiaG rehtoM otni ylbatrofmoc delttes eH
”?sseug ton uoy naC“
”.ecivda reffo nac I erofeb eciov ruoy raeh tsum I“ .dednammoc eh
,doog si retaw ehT“ .xoF dias ”,nisuoc ,knirD“
gnorw gnihton did uoY
,nerdlihc ruoy ot dna
”.emit fo dne eht litnu kram taht raew llahs nerdlihc s’nerdlihc ruoy dna nerdlihc ruoY
,ekoj a eb dluohs gnihtyreve toN“
kcor rehtona yb gnittis saw xoF ,hguone eruS
.noitcerid taht ni hgih ffo welf eH“
,niaga dna niaga enut elttil esraoh sih gnas nerw sutcac ehT
”,niav eb ot uoy detcepxe reven I“ .dehgual dna
,esirprus sih oT
.reh ot hsiw rieht repsihw meht tel ot ,eno yb eno
.rae reh otni gnihtemos dehtaerb eh dna
.evorppa dna raeh lliw tsael ta noom eht kniht I dna
.dehguoc dna deppots eH
.gnilkcuhc eht gniraeh llits saw eh dezilaer eH
.ylisae os ffo tup eb ot ton saw nevar yrgna ehT
”,nisuoc ,uoy fo revelc yrev woH“
.gninthgil tresed eht ekil decnuop dna eye sih fo edis eht fo tuo tnemevom a thguac etoyoC ,knird ot gnidneB
.drawhtron reve gnilevart ,skcossut dna dnas eht revo tort god a ta tuo tes eh
.thgilnus eht ni gnihsalf liat
sdileye sih dehcuot thgiL
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,dehcrep dah nevar eht erehw kcor llat eht yb dedahs
.ssucsid ot sgniht evah eW“
,lla evoba ytliug era uoY“ .deunitnoc aiaG ”,nevaR woN “
.nerw eht ot pu dellac dna
.retniw tsedloc eht dnatshtiw dluoc taht
.tem dah yeht erehw tops eht drawot kcab gnidaeh
.tuo gnignah tfel saw liat sih dna ,ecaps eht otni tif etiuq t’ndid eH
”?trap ruoy tuoba tahW“
,ksa uoy erofeb ylluferac knihT .os od llahs I
,mih ot regnarts on saw reppus tuohtiw
.gnikat saw eh noitcerid drawhtron emas eht ni gnilevart
,yad suoiverp eht fo nur gnol sih yb deneffits tlef eH
.tsap skeew ynam saw gnitsen rof emit eht hguoht neve
ecafrus eht ot delbbub sniatnuom hgih eht morf tlem wons erehw
.desucca eh ”,tsev der s’nevaR nelots evah uoY“
.yaw emas eht ni krow dluoc dnim nwo sih esuaceb won deirt eh kcirt yna hguorht ees dluow nevaR ,lla retfA
,ylthgil os reve srehtaef sih gnilffur
,srae sih revo ezeerb nmutua llihc a dna sdileye sih no nus eht tlef eh nehW
.resolc on werg sniatnuom eulb eht taht demees ti
niaga dnuorg eht otno nwod knas etoyoC
”,od nac uoy tahw em wohS“
.remaerd a saw ,revewoh ,etoyoC
,edart tsenoh na ekam ot deirt tsael ta etoyoC
,etoyoC htiw luftieced osla erew uoy tuB .edirp fo
.krab llirhs a saw ecudorp dluoc eh lla tub
,sevlesmeht gnideef fo ssenisub eht tuoba tnew retaw dna ,ria
.srehtaef thgirb dna sgniw rieht deviecer sdrib eht
eb nac xof a sa tnelis ,hsurbrednu eht hguorht ffo tperc xoF sa deciton meht fo rehtieN
.aiaG ta kool ot elbanu dna
,lleW“ gniralced erofeb niap ni decamirg eH
yawa sdray wef a tsuj
”.uoy pleh dna evigrof ot ydaL eht ksA“ .dezzub eh
.ti od ot yaw on ees dluoc tub
”.mih gnitcartsid rof uoy knahT
.ruf eht gnilffur
,mih ot railimafnu etiuq gnileef a ,ssenippahnU
.lla ta hgual ot denilcni ton m’I raf oS
taoc ruf hsul a tog floW
.xoF no ezag reh denrut aiaG nehT
.gnirps eht ni ylno sroloc thgirb eht raew yam uoy ,rebmemer tuB
.mih ot ekops eciov tfos a tub
,od uoy sa tnecifingam sa dnuos tonnac I wonk I
,uoy yarteb lliw tnecs ruoY
.gnitsaf llits dna erostoof devirra etoyoC dna
”.gnits eht fo emos tsael ta yawa ekat dluohs tI
.llew sa em dna sevlesruoy dessarrabme evah uoy fo owt eht tub
”.ti nelots dna mih devieced evah t’ndluohs I“
.deyebo lived der won eht
”?tresed eht fo god ,llew sa noob a ksa ot emoc uoy evah rO
,noziroh eht evoba llew doots won hcihw ,nus eht ot ecaf sih desiar etoyoC ”.llew yreV“
,etoyoC morf yawa degde nevaR
.nisuoc ,ni taht kaos ot retaw looc emos dnif ot uoy esivda d’I
”.snmyh ym htiw thgin eht ni noom eht dna
”,eno elttil ym ,esrow raf enod evah dluoc uoY“
.dlrow reh ni evil ot dna
,ylthgil liat sih dehcuot aiaG
”.hguoht ,stip eht fo ynam oot wollaws t’noD
.evila saw etoyoC dna
.nevaR ot reraen devom dna
.hcaer s’etoyoC nihtiw dnuorg eht no dnats ot nwod dedilg dna
,tsafkaerb rof gnikool tuohtiW
”?yltnecer mih nees uoy evaH“ .derewsna eh
”?os did I fi niagrab eht fo flah ruoy llifluf uoy dluoc woh ,lla retfA
.nekat dah nevar eht noitcerid eht ni elzzum sih htiw detniop etoyoC
.rafa morf draeh eb dluoc taht eciov gnignis detnelat a dah eh
.hsiw yreve detnarg dna
,lufituaeb flesti dlrow eht edam sgnos reH
.tsen sih rednu sehsub eht ni neddih ti dnif ot ysae saw tI
,stpmetta tsap sih htiw sa tub ,gnis ot deirt eH
.emirc siht timmoc ot uoy rof ysae ti gnikam
.gnirepmihw dna liat derujni sih ta gnikcil
.tib a tnap ot decrof saw etoyoC taht hguone ylkciuq dettort xoF
,mih no dehtaerb ehS
.dnuos eltneg dna thgirb a ,dehgual aiaG
,flesmih decap eH
?neht og eh did erehW“
daeh sih debbur ehs nehw neve ezag reh teem ton did tub
”?taht nrael uoy did woH“
.uoy esipsed dna uoy tnuh lliw srehto
.uoy fo eno yreve evol I taht rebmemer syawla tub
.taht otni tif ot dedeen retaw dna htrae eht fo slamina eht dna
,ecalp gnidih sti revo hctaw ot evah t'ndluow eh os nevaR rof tsev eht draug dna tcetorp dluoc uoY“ .derewsna etoyoC
.elttil a demmid seye s’nisuoc sih ni kraps eht fo emos taht etoyoC ot demees ti dna ,niaga daeh sih dekorts ehs
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,snaeco sti lla htiw ecnetsixe otni dlrow eht gnas aiaG rehtoM retfa
,stfig lanif reh tuo dessap aiaG erehw llonk elttil eht no tas eH
.hguoht em nihtiw gniworg tfig ruoy leef nac I“ .deksa eh
”,em detaehc eh ,lleW“
,uoy evag I tahw kcab ekat nac I tuB
.daeh sih koohs etoyoC
”?tfig s’aiaG erahs uoy nac woH“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.drib rehtona tub yna rof hcaer fo tuo
”.tsev deroloc enif sih rof noitcetorp naht rehto reffo ot elttil evah I dna tnemyap a sdnamed eH
.peels ot hsub egas a rednu delwarc eh os
.ksud eht otni ffo deksihw neht
.dias eh ”,kcab tsev sih evah nevaR tel ,oN“
,mih no dehtaerb dna
,denway dna dehcterts etoyoC sA
.enola uoy ot ti evag ehs yleruS“
”,ti fo esu doog evah uoy yam dna ,detnarG“
.tfig laiceps a deviecer ynaM
saw xoF .gnihtyna gniyas tuohtiw sniatnuom eht drawot kcab welf drib ehT
,retlehs ot ecalp a rof yletarepsed tuoba dekool xoF
,revoc rof kool ot gnirehtob neve tuohtiW
.efil tnalp dairym htiw dellif dna ,deroloc ylthgirb
.hgual t’ndid xof ehT .dekramer eh
”?em hcaet uoy lliW
.esnopser a deredisnoc eh sa tnemom a rof llol eugnot sih tel dna
”.snossel gnignis em evig ot mih tnaw I
.taorht sih ni enihw elttil a gnikam dna
.thguoht eh os rO
.setunim wef a retfa deksa etoyoC ”?lleW“ .teiuq yrev
”.deneppah tahw em lleT
.gniteem a ot meht gninommus
.thgir er’uoy esoppus I“ .dehgis xoF
nruter dluoc uoy gniwonk
,rebmetpeS ni gnineve looc a nO
.tuo uoy kees d'I thguoht I os ,yaw siht gnimoc erew uoy em dlot evod A“
seigrene s'etoyoC dehserfer taht looc tnasaelp a otni ffo llef yad eht fo taeh eht dna
mih edih dluoc taht sroloc fo erutxim a emaceb yalc wolley llud ehT
ecnatsid eht otni edaf xof eht dehctaw etoyoC .epol wols a ta
wons eht tsniaga retniw eht ni refas si tahT
.etam a sserpmi ot eb dluoc I emosdnah woh knihT
.sdrib erew ereht ,tresed sih ni nevE
.delims dna etoyoC ot denrut aiaG
.nus gnidnecsed eht ot lleweraf a gnis ot
,ecap ydaets a ta ffo koot sdinac owt ehT
:yojne esaelP .orevO ovitlA
,ytiniffaruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
ned nwo sih rof ffo tes xof eht ,taht htiW
knirhs eciov sih tlef eh sa
.ti dedeen eh nehw ylefas kcab ti evah d'eh dna
,htmraw s'nus eht dleh llits taht
,nus eht derevoc duolc A
,yad rehtona ecaf ot ydaer leef t’ndid eH
,swap kcab sih htiw dnuorg eht deffucs etoyoc ehT
”.nac uoy sa hcum sa erahs syawla dna
.roloc emas eht erew lla
”.diarfa eb t’nod dna llits yats tsuJ
,emas eht tsuj hsiw sih detnarg ehs tuB .mih dlot ehs
”?ton ti seod ,enim ti sekam noissessoP“
senips prahs eht gnoma dehcrep drib dettops eht
.daeh sih koohs eH
.owt ro ecap a yb resolc gnimoc erofeb dehcterts dna
.tcepser ni srae sih gnirewol
.emoc dah yeht hcihw morf dum eht ekil eugav erew sepahs rieht
”.ydaerla tsafkaerb dah I“
.tsehc dna taorht sih dettap dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,srevir dna sekal
.thgil mid ni neve mih yarteb dluow taht
,neht ecaf s’aiaG otni pu dekool etoyoC
,drawhtuos dettort eh sA
.dnuorg eht ta gnirats
.htiw gnis ot eciov a mih evig ro gnis ot mih hcaet t’ndluoc uoy wenk uoy esuaceb
.dnuora dekool aiaG
,srae s’etoyoC ssorca drah welb ehS
,swodahs tserof eht ni egalfuomac rof ,ees uoy nworb saw ruf siH
,tsud eht ni detcejed tis ot tfel eno eht won
”.rovaf ruoy ni elur lliw ehs dna
.rae reh otni gnihtemos dessih eh dna
deknilb eh dna taorht sih dehcuot ehS
,thgin taht sessarg yrd fo deb sih no dial eh sA
,noitatiseh feirb a retfA
.tser ot srewolf gnirps dna
.dias eh ”,ecivda dna gnihcaet ruoy rof ksa ot ,nevaR ,emoc evah I“
.taht ta hgual dluow etoyoC
sevooh drah sih nevig saw esroH
tnecsed s’nus eht fo roloc dna erif ehT
romuh fo esnes a
.xoF eht depacse rethgual fo krab A
.daeh sih koohs etoyoC
.gnirewsna erofeb etoyoC ta nwod dereep nerW sutcaC
.sdnal reneerg eht steem tresed eht erehw egde eht ta
.tey dellud yletelpmoc ton erew stiw sih taht dezilaer etoyoC .deksa eh
.mih dlot ydaL eht ”,won oG“
,htiaf doog ni detca dna ,llew did uoY
.gnignis deirt reven dah eh ,esruoc fO
,emoh sih drawot ffo nar xof eht ,yltneidebO
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.aiaG gnidrager seye wolley sih
ria eht fo sdrib ehT
.eviecer dluow yeht stfig eht meht ot gnas dna
reh ediseb tas eh oS
.ti peek llahs xoF ,etsaw ot og ton dluohs tsev der lufituaeb eht ecnis ,eromrehtruF“
.evig ot sih saw ti rof ,uoy evag etoyoC tahw kcab ekat tonnac I
,wenk eh ,taht did sdriB
,thgin eht rof tnew yeht reverehw edahs dna retaw eb dluow ereht taht wenk eH
.rennid eb lliw yeht ro
.tsirw reh no delttes dna
.dnuorg eht ta derats dna eciov reh ta decniw nevaR
,oraugas deromra ekips a fo pot eht ot gniylF
.ereht ydaL eht gnidnif fo sepoh ni tuo dessap erew stfig eht erehw ecalp eht rof tuo tes eh
,ecivda s’drib a gnikat yb ssem siht otni nettog dah eh
.uoy htiw enog evah thgim ti esrow hcum woh etaicerppa ot tfig s’etoyoC esU
.taht evoba esir nac uoy tub
,ylleb ytpme na dna
.ecno sgniw sih deppalf dna
.delbmur rednuht dna
,tops deretlehs sih morf deppets etoyoC
regnol on ecaep sih dloh dluoc eh yllaniF
.rof gnikool saw eh gniht emas eht ton ylniatreC
?ecneidua gnirimda nA“
.tfig lacigam reh fo trap tsol evah ot saw eh yrros woh htiw gnidne
.thgif dna nrut ton dluoc eh taht worran os saw nesohc dah eh eciverc eht tub
.sekal dna snaeco eht otni meht desaeler aiaG sa retaw eht ni kcus ot shtuom rieht gninepo
.aiaG ot hsiw sih derumrum eh sa
.rehto hcae tsniaga ylneknurd denael taht skcor owt rednu tops a otni delbbarcs ylkciuq dna
,reh ot meht fo hcae denommus dna
,xoF ot deddon etoyoC
,ssarg eht ni sehcnuah sih no tas dna
.siht ta yllufworros deddon xoF
.tnessa rieht deprihc sdrib ehT
.mih no seye sih tpek tub
,srae sih tsap derettulf nerw ehT
,nisuoc sih ekilnu tub ,syad esoht ni elagnithgin a ekil gnas nevaR
.won meht ees lliw I dnA
.dehcaer I tniop gnikcits eht s'tahT
.gnirit tuohtiw selim rof nur ot ytiliba eht dna
.nevaR ta tsrif dekool ehS
.srae sih ta kcep dna
.denway dna seye sih denepo eh erofeb yks eht otni tperc nwad eslaF
,dereffo ylgnilliw ,tfig sih koot uoy teY
,nus eht ni deird dna yalc morf edam erew yeht ecniS
,deirav smrof rieht hguohT
?kcab ti ekat drib diputs eht nac woH“ .deilper xof eht
.nus eht ni derettilg dna
,tnemtnioppasid fo enihw das a saw ekam dluoc eh dnuos ylno ehT
,stserof dna snialp ,sniatnuom
.noisired sih nwod dellac nevaR
.emit gnol a rof mih derednop aiaG rehtoM
orevO ovitlA yb ”ecioV s’etoyoC“
,seye reh ni kool das a htiw tub gnilimS
.hteet sih ni esuom taf eht
,yltnatculeR ”.ereh emoC“
nus tresed eht ni relooc mih peek dluoc taht ruf htiw
.og dluoc eh sa tsaf sa
.uoy htiw suoreneg oot spahrep saw I taht“ ,dias ehs ”,ees I“
.mih desivda rehtom eht
.deddon dna deknilb slamina ehT
.dniw dnoces a mih evag dna
.kcor eht ni skcarc hguorht nwod gnilkcirt retfa
.setunim lareves rof noitautis eht gnirednop
.ecrof yb stnelat sih kcab ekat ot mih rof yaw on saw ereht ,noitarepooc s’nevaR tuohtiw dnA
.rethgual emos sdeen dlrow eht taht eerga I tub“ ,dettimda ehs
.feihcsim dnif ot erus era swap eldi taht dna ,gniht doog a reven si gnikniht taht uoy llet dluow emoS
deksa uoy tahw htiw dedrawer era uoy os
,tfig eht ot deknil tcejbo lacisyhp on saw erehT
.srehto fo sesnes eht no skcirt suolevram yalp ot ytiliba eht dna
.oot dehsinav dah xoF taht dezilaer dna dnuora dekool eH
”,ylluferac taht deredisnoc evah I“
.efil fo htaerb eht dna ssenerawa meht gnivig
sutcac tnaig eht fo esab eht dnuora deddap eH
,nevaR morf kcab seitiliba revelc sih teg ot nalp a etalumrof ot deirt eh
.tnatsni na ni ecalp gnidih a gid osla dna
,xoF ta devid nevaR
.evol dna lavorppa reh fo htmraw eht tlef dna
.aiaG fo yaw eht si hcus rof ,ecnahc on dah esuom etanutrofnu ehT
,tfig suoreneg a em evag aiaG“ .deddon etoyoC
.taht ekil gnis ot erised eht htiw tsrub thgim traeh sih thguoht etoyoC
.deerga eh ”,thgir llA“
.dettimda eh ”,em htiw niagrab a ekam ot deirt xoF“
”,retal ro renoos ,lla su sdnif ecitsuJ“
.ylihtoot gninnirg erofeb maerts eht morf knard dna
thguoht eh tsrif tA
.yks gninethgirb eht tsniaga welf yeht sa yltfos deltrohc sevod ehT
,nevaR ot romuh fo esnes sih flah nevig ylurt dah eH