.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sussateM yb
”.niaga ti od ot gniog tsuj s’eh esuaceb
.fles enilucsam-os-reve ,nrobbuts lausu sih eb ot eunitnoc dluow dad taht—
nem ym wenk I ,ylikcuL
.won yb taht ot
,em sllac eh revetahw ro rotcod eht ro esrun eht eb ot gnidneterp
,etam yllis sih fo thgis eht ot detaert saw eh sa
.gnirac yrev eb nac eh semitemoS
,buc-elddim ruo ,ttaM deviecnoc ew kniht I
.ruf tuo-deffup ym nwod dehtooms dna srae ym neewteb ruf eht dehtooms ehs sa
:dluow ega taht fo buc yna gniht ylno eht did I .em revo dna
tnatropmi gnihtemos denrael dah I taht denialpxe anaN
,noitcif-orcim detimil-drow no neek ylralucitrap si eH
...renaelc muucav a esu ot woh ro
.seye s’tac a fo em dednimer syawla sessalg detniop yltniauq reH
,riahc eht morf nwod em depleh
.0 xeR ,1 eM .denrael nosseL
gnihtemos ,ereht gnihtemos saw ereht wenk I
!erehwyreve nwerts ogeL saw ereht—
.moor teiuq eht ni ,nwo sti no lla ,ereht gnittis dloc dna ylenol neeb evah tsum ti thguoht I
.eson ym ni hcir emufrep reh
,rehto eht ni redloh eldnac latsyrc a fo esab eht
.emoh eht evael ew emit hcae lanoitome yllaer teg I
,seldnac rof ti esu reven eW
,esab eht rof dehcaer I ,repmet ym nI
.pu naelc ot em rof tfel dah nem ym ssem tahw ees ot nehctik eht otni kcab tnew ew ,dnah ni dnah
hcuoc eht fo dne eht morf nekorb ton dah taht erawssalg fo eceip a pu dekcip ehS
thgir eht ,tfel eht ot
,elims tseteews ym htiw ,mih dlot I
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
ysae reven s’ti ,uoy llet I
.ecaf sih no nirg a ,swap sih dna trihs sih no sdus
,epip sih htiw hcrop eht no tas eh sa ,gnineve taht no retaL
!emoh ruo ni sdne reven ytrap ehT
,retsasid a tuohtiw etunim a naht erom rof enola meht evael dluoc I thguoht I nehW
,yllod derekcink-yllirf a tsuj naht elbat eht no sgniht erom evah thgim anaN thguoht reven I
sa erofeb naht regral hcum dna
:latsyrC drofretaW fo eceip lufituaeb a s’tI
.anaN htiw nehctik eht ni erew rehtoM dna yddaD
neercs VT suoicerp sih detaoc tsud ehT
.mih tih gnissap s’rehtoM drah woh morf ebyam
ffulf dna tsud htiw detaoc erew yeht
.flesym elosnoc ot etalocohc emos teg dna rorrim eht ni kool ytliug a flesym evig yllausu I os ,yawyna yenmihc eht rednu ti ees nac eno-oN
.oot dum ni gnillor devol eH
.reh tub enoyna ni tseretni na dah reven eh
,tsaf yrev dessergorp sah sremiehzlA s’yddad taht dias srotcod ehT
.dias ehs ,yrrow t’noD
.dnim ym fo htped eht morf ti gard ot deirt I sa tuo dna pu krej ot kcab ym no selkcah eht lla desuac—
riahc ediserif eht no pu bmilc ot dah I
.resolc dna resolc teg ot detrats yllod eht tub ,dnuorg eht ffo esir t’ndid I
.thgit ti dleh dna ti koot I
.esuoh s’anaN ta erew ew dna ,eerht ro owt ebyam
,moor gnivil ruo dnuora egnaro sehsalps nus gnittes eht nehw
,dlrow elttil ynit ym edisni tsol ,esruoc fO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dnah ym ni ssalg eht tlef I
.dexaler erom saw anaN tub
lausu reh ni tas
,eibbuh ym rof loot-rewop rehtona yub dluow eh niatrec saw I :ytterp
,wollip ym otni yrc em edam ti hguohT
.xelpmoc tnemeriter reh fo roolf dnuorg eht no tnemtrapa elttil yllirf dna taen yrev a ni devil ohw ,wodiw ylevil dna nrets a
.ti tuoba xeR gniggan pu dne d’I dna em otni tae tsuj dluow tI
,sgniht llams eht dna steknirt eht dehsilop I ,llitS
seirots erom roF
.ekat ot drah s’tahT
.moor gnivil eht otni retsud wolley gib ym koot I
.meht ta dniw ffo gnittel … meha
,riahc ym no seot-pit no doots I sa ,revewoH
,spuccih otni dedisbus sliaw ym litnu
.htaerb yreve htiw gnisigolopa tbuod on
.mih etad ot tnaw I gnikniht ,snirg eh dna
,yad ralucitrap eno sihT
.rettam t’nod yllaer stcejbo taht gnisilaer
,nedrag eht fo flah htiw moor eht sllif dna ruf sih sffup sanoJ nehw semitemoS
,hcuoc tfos ylevol eht referp t’ndid ehs yhw dnatsrednu t’ndluoc I dna
,llams yrev saw I
.em ta gnilims erew seye-stac reh dna tfos saw ecaf s’anaN
.em ot kcab emac ti ,ecno ta lla
,latsyrc fo eceip dilos ,dnuor ,egral a saw tI
.peelsa llef I litnu esolc em degguh eh
deggut I .hguone noos tuo dnuof I tub
.yrasrevinna tsrif ruo rof su ot ti evag rehtaf yM
,gnillevart saw eh nehw reh tnes yddad taht secalp yawaraf morf sllod
)!retsud tsrif eht tsac nis tuohtiw si ohw ehs teL(
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy
… yb meht yrd ot gnivah tuohtiw yawa meht tup dna
racsO ta delley I yaw emas eht ni mih ta gnilley ekil tlef I
.deifitrom eb dluow I dna
,gniraews deppots yeht nehW
,ssenrednet s’anaN yb dehcuot dna
deneppah ti sa ,ylnekatsim—demussa dah I dna
,mih rof traeh fo egnahc egnarts a saw tI
.traehteews elttil ym ,thgirla er’uoy taht si tnatropmi tsom s’tahW
)!taht od ot dewolla m’I .rethguad ylno sih m’I( .mih dezziuq I
,truhnu saw lrig ylno sih deveiler
.nekorb s’ti dnim t’now eh dna
.moc.sussatem no ro
.toos fo stums ni semoh ylevol rieht derevoc taht ekoms kcalb dirca fo sduolc eht rof su gnivigrof otni sruobhgien ruo mrahc ot owt ro buc etuc a fo htrib eht koot ti hguoht—
.ssalg fo edam eslE-gnihtemoS egral a saw sa
.eldnac a tes uoy hcihw otni ertnec eht ni elpmid a htiw
.mosob ycal reh ot esolc em degguh dna hcuoc eht no nwod tas neht dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.enod htrae no krow sih redisnoc dna
.esrun sih m’I skniht eh emit eht fo tsoM
emoh kcab tnew I nehW
,ereht saw eh desilaer I tub ,yad eht fo yromem ym ni mih gniees llacer t’ndluoc I
,sih fo yaw ffurg taht ni dennirg tsuj eH
,4 .loV gnaF ni ,enizagam nocorhtnA eht ni
sgniht ytterp eht lla naht buc elttil denethgirf a ot erom naem lliw ssenrednet dna
.yvaN eht ni saw eh nehw detisiv eh sdnal eht lla tuoba em dna srehtorb ym llet dna
.em tnuah ot kcab emoc dluow ti taht wenk I
.tuo ti tros nac eh os ,em deirram eh taht mih dlot dna
deb eht fo dne eht ta tis dluow eh nehw sthgin retniw yllihc eht lla dna ,occabot gnibbur
.eromyna ma I ohw wonk ot mees t’nseod eh tub
,daeh yerg sih koohs dad dna
.ni dehsad rehtoM dna anaN erofeb dessap sdnoces wef a ylno taht ylekil erom s’ti tub
,ecal etihw psirc
.esab latsyrc a no stis taht yenmihc latsyrc ylevol a sah tI
syawla ehS .sregnif dnomla dna secils maerc
,sdrow ni llacer t’nac uoy taht dnik eht
.redloh eldnac ym no detrats neht
.rac eht otni teg ew nehw esolc em sguh dna ,swonk xeR tuB
.erusaert elttil ym
,)mih morf yad yreve dna hcae sllac enohp ytnewt ro net retfa(
.gnineve siht ot kcab ,yawynA
.sussateM ecalperif eht fo dneirf yb ”latsyrC“
,ruof saw I nehw yawa deid ehS
riahc hgih dekcab-thgiarts
,eetnaraug nac elamef ahpla yreve sa
sgnitirw sih daer nac uoY
.keew lluf a rof rehtom ym htiw yats ot tnew I ffo dna
.ytiniffA ruF no puorg "tpmorP yadsruhT" eht fo trap sa
.snoihsuc detehcorc htiw dellif
,ssalg tuc fo eceip yvaeh elgnis a si trap tahT
.gnola emac sbuc eht erofeb ,deirram ew retfa tsuj ,ecno god tep a dah eW
,seceip ni dehsams saw daeh-anihc s’yllod ehT
”,eniF“    .thgiR .ahA
elbat eht ot revo deknils I rebmemer I
,hsarc suomrone na htiw
.stib ot meht evol I dna ,kcap yppah a er’ew tub
desu llew m’I .meht no klaw uoy fi truh yllaer nac yehT
sgnineve remmus mraw esoht no yllaicepse ,yllufituaeb
os gnihtemos esohc yddad yhw derednow netfo I
,pu gninaelc ni tniop on s’erehT
”latsyrC“ saw sihT
,)txen pu kniht ll’eh tahw swonk ylno nevaeh esiwrehto
si yrots s’yadot dna
nrecnoc fo kool ot degnahc tI
.taht od yehT .god a s’racsO“
.citnamor dlo sselepoh uoy ,yddaD
dum fo syoj eht derevocsid yltnecer sah ,tsegnuoy ruo ,sanoJ
tac denethgirf a ekil pu ffup uoy sekam ti tub
,ssorca sehcni xis tuoba
,ksum fo sllems eh guh eyb-doog a mih evig I nehW
...rehtaf s’buc eht tuoba swal hcus yna s’ereht fi erus ton m’I hguoht ,lennek a ni edistuo buc tsegnuoy ruoy gnittup tuoba ecalpemos wal a ylbaborp s’ereht ,yldaS
ertnec eht ni elpmid elgnis a htiw
.moor gnivil eht ni elbat derevoc-ecal a no gnittis yllod elttil lufituaeb a saw ereht
,dna hguone raf gnihtyreve
,emoh dezis-egareva a ni sevlow llams eerht dna nworg-lluf owt gnivah ,egnellahc laer a eb nac ti—
kcab emit emos gnitirw detrats sussateM ,dnalerI fo tsew dliw eht ni desaB
.rehtegot yalp dluoc ew dna retsis ym eb dluoc ehs ,ti hcaer tsuj dluoc I fI
,moor gnivil eht otni emac xeR
.yawa raf yrev demees lla straf dna gnihsawhsid ,ylnedduS
eveileb ot drah s’tI
klat sih lla htiw tub ,mih llac ot desu rehtoM ,lived dlo ytriD
,em sehtoos tnecs siH
meht fo 563 evah ll'eh tniop emos tA
,dew I dna xeR retfa shtnom evif emos yawa dessap dah rehtoM
yad ylevol taht gnirebmemer ,won pu gniraet m’I
,sevlesmeht retfa moorhtab eht naelc ot meht hcaet ot yaw a erugif dluoc I ylno fi woN
.yllod eht guh ot detnaw I esuaceb ,yawa dekaens dna depacse dah I
.railimaf ylegnarts tlef tI
,ytinrete na rof roolf eht no gnittis saw I ekil tlef tI
,sraet ym hguorht trotsid dna rulb moor eht gnihctaw dna tuo seye elttil ym gnilwab
.tsud htiw yhtlif saw ti desnes I
.thgir saw eh kniht I
ti ta thgir kool dluow yeht dna ,gnihtemos ro sknird rof revo enoemos llat yllaer a evah d’eW
.yrrow htiw denil secaf elttil rieht
xeR ta thgir dekool
.gniddew ruo rof did eh ekil
.ffo sliat elttil rieht gnilwoh erew yeht gniwonk
)llaw eht no detnuom dna deffuts mih evah d’I ,esuoh s’wal-ni-rehtom ym ni siht ekil gnihtemos did starb elttil nwo ym fo eno fi dna(
.rednelb na ni eehsnab a ekil delwoh dna sdrahs eht fo elddim eht ni nwod tas I
— elbat eht fo egde eht revo deruop sgniht ynihs rehto dna erawssalg ,semarf otohp ,sexob-ffuns fo aragaiN a
.seceip ssalg eht rof hcaer ot
.nwod epiw a esab eht evig ot dediced I neht dna ,emoc ot s’tahw dna neeb sah tahw fo gnikniht
enif saw gnihtyreve
.evol ,ereht erehT    .em dettep dna pu em dekcip ehs
?lrig doog s’anaN eb I dluoW    .anaN ,oN
.si ehs erehw eb ot naht erom gnihton stnaw yllaer yddad skniht eh
,tfig yrasrevinna hteitfif ruo rof em dna daddnarg ruoy tog yddad ruoy tfig a saw tahT
.worromot on ekil tuo seye reh gnibbulb
tespu ylbirret saw rehtoM
yltfos daeherof ym dessik ,thgit em degguh
,wonk uoy—yromem fo elgnit A
.dnuora gnimaercs sbuc dliw ruo htiw ton ylniatrec
.lufesu gnihtemos fo daetsni ytterp gnihtemos gniyub
”latsyrC“:yojne esaelP
.dlrow eritne eht ni
!noitavrats htiw meht netaerht I revenehw ti ot pmuj yehT
,dnalrednow ym saw emoh reH
,pu lla ti ydit dna sdnema ekam ot gniyrt ,tuoba deltsub rehtoM
.yad emos wonk d’I dias dna
.em ot ti dednah dna
dna srewolfnus ,enihsnus dna sevil ysub fo em gnidnimer
.erew yddaD ro rehtoM erehw wonk regnol on I
esuoh a dna ,dray eht ni tuo lennek wen-dnarb sih ni ylippah gnivil god eht dnuof I
.sllaw etihw eht revo
.meht gnihctaw ton m’I nehw thgila ecalp eht gnittes dna saedi gnitteg meht tnaw t’nod I
drow evitarepo eht gnieb stiB
,dna ecalperif eht revo flehs sti no degnarra saw erawssalg etiruovaf yM
,ylluferac edisa yenmihc eht tup I oS
.sehsid fo lluf saw knis nehctik eht dna ,em rof enihcam eht yb gnihsaw sih tfel eh eciton did I hguohtla—
,srettam evol ,rettam nerdlihC
.llew gnitae s’eh fi mih ksa dna
.ylreporp elbat eht gniraelc otni meht gniregdab saw I dna
?racsO tcive eh did yhw oS
.yadretsey saw ti fi sa raelc sa reh tuoba gnihtyreve llacer I tub
ssik a mih evig I ,og ew nehW
thgil eht sehctac ssalg ehT
.tif dluoc eldnac a erehw
taht thgin eno dias etam yM
,yrettilg dna thgirb-revo demees moor ehT
?niaga shtolcelbat ta llup reve I dluoW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
ruoloc fo swobniar thgirb gnivael
”!ytsgip eht ni evil nac uoy“
,taht od ot evah uoy(
,xeR sesingocer semitemos yddaD
,mom s’yddad saw anaN
.draykcab eht ni detamerc xeR dna yddad eucebrab eht fo hcnets eht neve—
.dnah ym ni ssalg yvaeh eht dleh I
,yenmihc ssalg eht dehsilop I sa niarb ym hguorht nar sthguoht eseht llA   .emoh og ew nehT
.sbuc ruo dna ,xeR etam ym htiw nehctik eht ni saw I
."selaT droW 563" meht gnillac
.em dna anaN tsuj won saw ereht seiromem ekildlihc ym nI
.pu ydit ot tnaw t’nod yeht fi
!tes-aet ym htiw aet evah dluoc ew dna yllod ym eb dluow ehS
.nehctik eht ni somanyd elttil ruo gnillet saw eh tahw desilaer I nehw ,em pleh emoc ot niahc-dna-llab ym llac ot tuoba tsuj
,elims nedlog a htiw keehc ym fo ruf pmad eht dekorts ehS    .anaN ,seY
.ereht erehT
!denrecnoc era starb elttil esoht erehw kwah a ekil eb ot uoy evah uoY
.ekatsim yb retnirp sih no yllanoisacco dna
,gnikooc ym evol yeht tub—
,dnah eno ni retsud ,riahc a no gnidnats
.taht ekil yad a evah niaga reven ylbaborp ll’ew taht
etam ylevol ,rednet ,lufrednow yM
,deniur saw rehtaf etal sih dna rehtom sih rof nesohc dah eh ytterp gnihtemos fo tfig eht taht deyonna
,rood nehctik eht dnuora deretsulc sbuc lufituaeb ,lufrednow ruO
,smedaid ytterp fo lluf
ruf dehs ,skcos ,sretaews ,srekaenS
,rehto ro gnihtemos tuoba gnihgual erew eW
.sbuc depahs-lerrab elttil ruo
.evol ,srettam tahw dnatsrednu t’nod neM
.thgin txen yrev eht
,neht ,ytinrete rehtona rof em degguh
.llabtoof eht hctaw t’ndluoc eh dna
.ti tuoba wonk I nehw taht ekil gniht a evael t’nac I
.ti naelc ot rehtob ylerar I pleh tuohtiw ti hcaer ot trohs oot m’I sa tub ,siht timda ot dessarrabme m’I
.esac ni tsuj nevo eht ni gnihtemos deraperp dah dna
,neht dnA .nettogrof dah I
,egakaerb rojam ro tnemugra
,su ot ti detneserp eh nehw sraet otni tsrub I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ten.ytiniffaruf no yhpargotohp sih weiv dna
deraeppa sah krow siH
elbirret oot t’nsaw taht
.flesmih sekahs dna ffo seird eh nehw erehwyreve tsud s’ereht ro gnihsurb hguoroht a sgel dna smra sih evig ot evah I edistuo morf ni semoc eh revenehw dna
gnikooc pots ot yppah naht erom m’I dna
.erofeb yad eht tsuj gnihtyreve denaelc ylluferac dah I hguoht neve—
,si eh taht nam ylevol ,xeR
reh ot em dleh ehS
setalp hsaw ot woh no
.sthgieh htiw taerg ton m’I dna ,ees nac uoy sa ,llat taht lla ton m’I
”!taht ekil sgniht yas t’noD !xeR“ yrosruc a mih evag I
sbuc eht gnitcurtsni ylluferac saw eH
.nwod ti detfil dna ti debbarg
.)god ruo saw taht(
?rewsna s’dnabsuh ruf-fo-llab-sselhtrow-gnihton-rof-doog yzal ym ,neht kcaB
,nac I tseb sa elims I
,rennid retfa tsuj gnineve sihT   sussateM yb
.htolcelbat ecal dehcrats lufituaeb eht pu bmilc ot detrats dna