".truh steg ohw tuoba
.ot dedeen I sa ynam sa ylnO"
,siht ekil elbat a raen flesmih dnuof eh emit yrevE
,alotsaB anyaR saw ehs detroper ti retal sdnoces wef A
.aet dehcuotnu ,dloc fo spuc owt dna ,top
,selbategev fo erutxim thgirb a
,desolc rood eht sa noos sa atruk sih fo tuo deppirts ihsoM
.melborp eht evlos ot erusserp fo tol a gnitteg erew setanidrobus s'aerdnA fo lla dna
.aet sih deppis ihsoM ".skaerb
.oihO tsewhtuos fo tatibah elbanoitseuq eht morf flow detniap suoiragerg a
,noissim siht koot eh fI
.reh revo egarevel hcum oot mih evig dluow ylnepo taht gniwohs tub
".taht ssucsid yllaer t'nac I"
.tcirtsid evitartsinimda s'anelakaV ni llaH dnarG eht fo ybbol eht ni dworc gnirehtag eht denioj yehT
.ylthgil ylimaf tisiv ot eno ton saw dneirf doohdlihc remrof siH
.yllatnem dedda ihsoM ,su rof dnA ".tcejorP
.elbissop sa tiurf hcum sa tae dna locotorp kaerb ot tniop a ti edam eh
.woleb raf gnirekcilf sthgil mid eht ta nwod derats dna wodniw eht sdrawot denrut eh ,nehT
,uoy ekil ,esuaceB"
.ihsoM no detarg roivaheb ehT
"…snerraW ehT ni tnalp noitamalcer retaw a derevocsid smaet yevrus ruo fo enO"
.flodnaL tub enoyreve eraps dluoc eh
.ediw swap sih gnidaerps
,gnineve siht dehsilpmocca saw tahw rettam oN
.noziroh eht dellif aes eulb a dna
.ot klat ot esle enoemos tnaw tsuj I .erehwoN"
,deilper ihsoM ",ma'am ,uoy knahT"
.deksa anyaR "?klat ti seoD"
.dleifelttab siht no eulav lacitcat suomrone dah detamitserednu gnieb
.htuom s'aneyh eht ni llor teews eht ta ylgnisucca wap etihw a gnitniop
noitasrevnoc a saw tI .noitcerider s'ecyoJ rof lufknaht ,noitasrevnoc eht tuo denut ihsoM ".noitatnemgua
"?gnikrow sFAE NDNG eht gnitteg kcul yna dah tnemtraped ruoy saH
ytterp klat dna kcocaep tep a ekil dnuora turts ot evah I thginot esuaceB
dna epytotorp elbaiv tsrif rieht gnikam retfa tcejorp eht delecnac yeht ,oS
eugnot sih no reppep dna nomel fo elgnit eht deyojne ihsoM
,neeb syawla dah eh sah emas eht saw ihsoM taht decnivnoc yawa deklaw nahtaN
,deilper eh ,eniw fo pis a gniwollaws retfA
.esle enoyreve htiw emit ni sih desiar eh
.esu elbat eht ta snamuh eht nees dah eh erutseg a ni drawrof wap nepo na devaw neht dna rae na dekcilf ihsoM
.elbat eht ediseb muidop eht ot pu deppets-
.esabatad lacol eht ni reh dnif ot ti deksa dna margorp noitingocer laicaf sih pu dellup eh os
,neht neve tuB" .dewollaws eH ".loot
.snoitaluclac nwo sih did eh sa ecyoJ no seye sih dleh eH
.taeper ot erised on dah dna erofeb semit ynam ni neeb d'eh
.seiratingid ressel eht htiw selbat fo nmuloc driht eht fo dne eht ta detaes erew yehT
.ylkciuq derevocer dah ehS
.ecnatculer rof ecnelis sih degdujsim dah ehs dezilaer ihsoM dna dias ecyoJ
.tcejorP eht rof raey doog a neeb sah sihT
.thgin eno tsuj naht erom rof deyats evah dluoc tijaB taht dehsiw eH
.enips sih nwod elbmur
.revoekat IA tsniaga denedrah dna stnenopmoc NDNG tuohtiw tliub ti fo llA
.dnik sih htiw llet ot drah os s'tI
.noitcerid s'aneyh eht ni lworg a ot ti ecuder ot deganam eH
,eulb ni desserd ,settesor ro stops htiw klof derruf enilef fo yteirav a erew sretiaw eht ,esirprus s'ihsoM oT
ecuas etalocohc a ni delzzird niatnalp deirf fo seceip eerht
,noacyL edoyaK yb
.skaerb tnatropmi gnihtemos erofeb owt ro htnom a tog ev'I ,taht tuohtiW
.kniht I ,snoitatneserp retteb eht fo enO"  .ti gnilgnatnu
.tuo uoy erugif t'nac I"
.seno nworb ,tfos ylevitpeced reh teem ot seye dlog ,thgirb sih denrut dna elims thgils a deganam eH
.noitautis eht etalacse ylbissop dluoc dna
.thgil wolley ni gnihtyreve gnihtab
"?evael tsuj uoy t'nod yhw
,kcehc ni cinap yratnemom sih gnipeeK
.nocilis edarg hgih gnitteg ytluciffid emos saw ereht denoitnem eh
;enif tsuj god detniap eht detius ekatsim tahT .scitenrebyc dna
.tsiaw sih dnuora parw esool eht yb ylno derevoc flesmih gnivael
",siht fo ssem a gnikam m'I .yrros m'I"
.smraf eht kcatta taht senord tabmoc eugor eht retnuoc ot gnihtemos dedeen yehT"
,dnik ruo fo eno htiw nuf elttil a evah ecnahc eht detcepxe I ebyaM
.noitcelfed s'nahtaN gnigdelwonkca yltnelis-
dna suoregnad oot saw IA
.aneyh eht ot txen tas dna llor teews a dekcip god detniap ehT ".flesruoy
liat derruf a htiw libreg deroloc-ydnas A
.elbaeerga gnieb rof
.ti no delbbin dna krof sih htiw reppep neerg a debbats ihsoM
.sreffo eh secivres eht ni ekatrap ot rehtob neve t'nod uoy dna ,moor ruoy ni etutitsorp gnilliw yltcefrep a evah uoY
.esoprup rehtona dah oot siht tuB
,enoyna dellik reve dah uoy fi dnA"
.gnitseretni eb dluohs thginot renniD"
.snoissucreper sti dna raw ot ecnerefer dedile yletilop-erom-neve na dna
.yltfos ekops dna deppis tijaB ".noitseuq
.arabmA ot nwod sdaeh eh erofeb yromra eht ni ihsoM nioj ot emit txen ni enuT
.sdnah rieht naelc ot slewot eht desu srehtO
.enigne ytivargitna erutainim a no elbat eht revo gnirevoh
.dellif flah saw moor eht
?uoy ot rettam ti dluohs tahW"
,yzah ssel neeb dah weiv eht fI
.dellik flodnaL gnivah ni detseretni yrev eb lliw ehs kniht I"
.ecnanetniam deen em fo strap latem esoht dna latem dna hself fo tuo ydob ym edam yehT .t'nac I"
.kaeps ot flesmih tsurt t'ndid eh fi sa ,deddon ihsoM "?tnenamrep
teprac kciht eht otni ylpeed knus teef erab sih fo swalc dna sdap ehT
seirots s’édoyaK fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,tenalPruF yb
elttil a gnihtemos rof gnikool snamuh fo edarap tnatsnoc eht htiw derit elttil a teg I tub ,eruS"
.rioN toniP fo ssalg der peed a mih thguorb erofeb morf derebmemer ihsoM libreg ehT
.daer ot ysae oot tsomla demees semulov esoht ,tcaf nI
.doof deen yletarepsed ohw elpoep gnipleh si 'tsirorret' siht dna
.detsif erab yllauqe saw deilper reH
,tsrif ekops ihsoM
",sllems era sllemS"
;slliw fo tsetnoc tnatalb a trats dna —tnelis gniyats
# # # .slliks yraniluc evah dluow rennid eht gniraperp sfehc eht ,yllufepoH
.gnihtyna etaicerppa ylreporp ot emit hguone reven saw erehT
,noacyL édoyaK yb
,deb eht no rehtegot deldduh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitceridni siht fo derit gnitteg yllaer saw god detniap ehT ".kniht
em esoohc yeht ,os
,mih dlot tsuj ehS
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.rennuts laruen a htiw tuo meht fo lla dekconk eh ,nruter rieht rof gnitiaw retfA
.detseretninu eb ot gnidneterp ,reh gniwollof srae sih
.tfird noitnetta sih tel dna sih deppis ihsoM
.ecnelis tneitap fo teltnuag eht nwod werht dna evissapmi ecaf sih tpek eH ".ihsoM ,srennaM"
.setalp deraelc no meht decalp dna slewot dellor ylthgit tuo thguorb sretiaw ehT
,iras reh tuo dehtooms yldetniop ehS
.deppans god detniap eht
.noitseuq taht ksa t'nod uoy yhw wonk d'uoy
.elbat daeh eht ta detaes gnieb erew
".fo ssem a gnikam seiranecrem tnaw t'nod yeht taht smelborp eht evlos I" "?si hcihW"
.wodniw eht tuo gnirats ,deb sih no taes sih morf devom t'ndah ihsoM ,tfel tijaB retfa sruoH
.loot lufesu a eb ot em dnif srehtO .ytisoiruc a m'I
.draobssehc lacitilop eht no nwap a ot ytisoiruc erem a morf detaudarg dah eh ,noissim taht fo htamretfa eht nI
.flesruoy yrrac uoy woh tuoba lla s'tI"
.deksa namow rehto ehT "?tuB"
.srednatsyb etanutrofnu gnillik snoislupmoc on evah dluow esle enoemoS
.thgin elgnis a tsuj naht erom rof noitnetta ruoy dloh nac taht enoemos dnuof yllanif I dalg m'I"
.sregnif emos sunim
,llems eht naht rehtO"
".esle gnihtyna nwonk reven ev'I"
.sreyal retuo sih evomer ot eciohc s'ihsoM gnizisahpme fi sa
.tniop siht ezisahpme ot god detniap eht ta ti detniop dna yart eht ffo llor teews rehtona debbarg eh nehT
.moor eht fo edis eno dellif ,selbategev dna tiurf htiw nedal ylivaeh ,elbat tsav A
.eunitnoc t'nseod melborp siht os ,nosaes gniworg txen eht retfa doof erom dnes ot yraterceS eht teg dna dnuora siht nrut nac I ,noitauqe eht morf meht evomer nac ew fI
—reh rorrim dluoc eH
.tcejorP noitamalceR eht yb enod krow dleifneerG era erawtfos dna erawdrah yM .oN"
.yannodrahC yrd a rof tuo dedart saw ésoR eht dna spuc puos ytpme decalper ecuttel yfael fo deb a no hsif dellirg ykalf fo tellif llams a htiw setalP
.noitamrofni evitisnes s'tahw wonk syawla t'nod I
.stnadnetta yb detaes erew gnihtolc etarobale ylgnisaerced ni snamuh tnatropmi gnisaercni fo spuorg llams sa gnol saw tiaw ehT
,elppaenip fo tuo edam anelakaV
"?ssem siht fo lla otni tif I od erehw ,oS"
.yldrawni delims tub lassimsid ni wap a devaw ihsoM ".noitamrofni
# # # .trop yrrehc a htiw deriap
.sekat ti tahw s'taht fI"
.ereh uoy nees ev'I ecnis gnol oot raf neeb sah ti ,nahtaN"
.eciov wol a ni deksa eh
.seye sih dellor tijaB
,yaw eltbus nwo reh ni
,reldnah ruoy yB"
.retal weiver ot yromem retupmoc sih ot gnihtyreve dedrocer eH
—etamitse lanretni sih yb
.dewollof daerb detsaot no etopmoc otamot dna eseehc debreh fo etalp A
.ydit dna taen sgniht sekil ehS
.edisni peed tlef eh regna eht no nwod tib dna kcab daeh sih denael ihsoM ".detlusni
;daeh sih koohs yllatnem tub ecneirepxe eht fo ytlevon eht derovas ihsoM
.tniop siht ta snoitpo fo rebmun a saw erehT
.krow fo tol a ekil sdnuos tahT"
.htiw deniart dah eh snugliar thgil eht naht yldaed ssel on tub
.anyaR sdrawot denrut dna noisserpxe suoires yletairporppa na dekcip god detniap ehT  .dias ehs
.mrah hcum oot meht desuac slamina dliw ro erusopxe erofeb deucser eb dluoc yeht os noitacol rieht htiw seilimaf rieht fo eno dellac eh ,anelakaV ot denruter eh nehW .sseccus sih fo ecnedive sa meht fo hcae morf regnif a dna sknilmoc rieht evomer dna
,tiurfrats htiw etalp dedlig sih delip eh ,elihwnaeM
.gniylper erofeb tnemom a rof thguoht ecyoJ ".arabmA
.nwoD arabmA fo ytic eht ffo detnilg thgilnus ,tsaoc eht gnolA
,esolc a ot werd hceeps eht sA
.eciov sih fo tuo msacras eht peek ot lortnoc-fles fo derhs tsal yreve koot tI ".snoitacilpmoc
.wenk ydaerla eh sgniht demrifnoc taht srewsna wollahs tub erecnis htiw tem saw tahT
.delims yllautca anyaR
.dethgiled eb d'I ,esruoc fO"
".flesym rof edam ev'I tahw si evah I ytingid elttil tahW
.edart ot reffo na tcaf ni saw mih rof nosiail gnineve na fo eciohc reh ni tseretni dlim siH
.doom eht nethgil ot tpmetta deliaf a ni deksa aneyh depirts ehT
,gnipeels thgin eht tneps ylpmis dah yeht daetsnI
"…tcejorP noitamalceR dna yevruS arabmA eht fo gnidnuof eht ecnis raey hteitnewt eht skram yadoT
,daerb talf ytlas dna sevilo yreppep eht no delbbin eH
.ylthgils os reve hctiwt htuom s'ecyoJ was eh ,eye sih fo renroc eht nI ".su
.nwoD arabmA fo klof derruf eht htiw pihsnoitaler lainegnoc erom a rof hsup dluoc eh
.reh fo noitaulave sih desaercni ihsoM
,dlog dna eulb layor ni
.cidica ylgnitnioppasid dnuof eh hcihw
,waj sih dniheb selcsum eht dedaenk yltrepxe dah sregnif gnorts riehT
.aet fo puc a ruop ot deb eht no yart eht ot revo devom eh dna denettalf srae s’ihsoM
.tnegnup dna ruos saw gnisserd eht ,thgiled sih oT
.htlaeh rieht tuoba gniksa yb hcnarb evilo lacirohpatem eht dnetxe ot saw pets txen ehT
.taht tsuj od ot yaw sih no ytinamuh fo sroloc ynam eht yb dessap ihsoM
.ssarg hannavas llat eht ni gnikrul srotaderp eht fo erawanu dnuora gniklaw epoletna lufssilb a naht erom gnihton saw nahtaN
.nosaes gniworg txen eht fo noissucsid a no tuo deretep noitasrevnoc ehT
.woleb raf nwoD arabmA ta wodniw eht tuo derats ihsoM ".ot
",eH"  .demialcxe ehs
.ti od dluow eh wenk htob yehT
".ytingid fo ngis a si ssenetiloP"
,flesruoy ecap dnA"
.reh nioj ot detivni gnieb fo
.ssenevitnetta sih rof tniop a mih gnidrawa
”ekaL nedraG kraD“   yojne esaelP
,noacyL édoyaK yb
.noitseuq gnorw eht yltcaxe gniksa erofeb puc sih ta derats aneyh depirts ehT
evitnecni na htob sa tijaB gniredisnoc ylbaborp saw ecyoJ
.anyaR htiw noitasrevnoc s'ecyoJ no rae na gnipeek elihw eniw sih gnippis dna rebmucuc fo stib eht dnuora gnitae
.esol dluow kaeps ot eno tsrif eht
.teews yldlim dna ,yrd ,gnorts
.mrala ni pu dekrep srae s'tijaB "?seiranecreM"
.tsugsid ni elknirw ecaf reh edam tnecs gniregnil s'tijaB .noixelpmoc krad dna esiop looc reh htiw llew dehctam taht esuolb sseleveels neerg a erow ehS
.mih revo denael hateehc a dna ssalg sih dellifer
.selbat eht sdrawot ssalg reh gnisiar saw muidop eht dniheb namuh eht dna retaw sih decalper dah ssalg eniw A
"?anihcaM eht yb revo nekat gnieb uoy tuoba yrrow I dluohs ,oS"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.peels dluoc eh os htiw revo lla siht teg ot tnaw tsuj mih edam ylleb lluf a dna
".em rof esu retteb a evah yeht litnu llif dluoc I elor rehto emos dnuof
.ti tsniaga kcilc dna pmuj meht edam noitarbiv eht
,saw ehs ohw erus t'nsaw eH
"?ledom sih fo selamef yna evah uoy oD
strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
cnalB nongivuaS fo ssalg a rof dedart saw ssalg eniw ytpme s'ihsoM
,riah reh hguorht regnif reh nar dna sriahc eht fo eno fo mra eht no tas ehS
",gnirepmap htiw melborp a evah ot mees t'nod uoY"
.tibdit lufesu a saw ereht yllanoisacco tub klat eldi saw ti fo tsoM
.ni netsil ot deunitnoc dna etalp a debbarg ihsoM
.senibmoc s'erutlucirgA fo tnemtrapeD eht rof erawtfos wen ssucsid ot pu kcab noitasrevnoc eht dekcip ecyoJ ".evorppa
.drows a htiw gniddorp fo daetsni kcor a gniworht fo tnelaviuqe eht saw yltcerid ti yas ot tub
.elims derusaem ,etilop a htiw dias eh
emag regral eht fo erawanu yletelpmoc rehtie saw nahtaN
.dewehc eh sa wodniw depols eht fo emarf eht tsniaga kcab depirts sih denael eH
erom elttil a gnihtemos egnarra nac ew spahreP"
".fo erac nekat sdeen taht melborp a sah aerdnA yraterceS
.nemeltneg dna seidal demeetse ruo ,gnineve dooG"
.sap xuaf laicos a saw sretiaw eht ot noitaredisnoc yna gniwohs taht raeppa dluow tI
.denetfos ecaf s'ecyoJ
.ytterp erew yeht tub
.steerts laudividni weiv ot erawtfos gnicnahne egami sih desu evah dluoc ihsoM
.mih ta dnah a gnivaw dias ecyoJ
nomannic fo tnecs eht derewoprevo aneyh tew eht fo llems dicnar ehT
.seimene gnikam dnim t'ndid uoy sa gnol sa
dessim yletelpmoc rehtie saw sap xuaf laicos etarebiled siH
"?anelakaV ot uoy sgnirb tahW
.gnitseretni teg ot gnitrats saw gnippordsevae siH
.detnaw eh noitseuq eht ksa dna gnihtyreve pord t'ndluoc eh ereh nevE
,deen naht tibah fo tuo eroM
.evorppa ll'ehs kniht I tub aerdnA htiw siht ssucsid ot deen esruoc fo ll'I"
.deb eht etisoppo riahc ksed eht no tas dna deffuh ehS ".lavomer
,emoserit ylbidercni neeb ydaerla dah renniD
.elbuort esuac ot esucxe na rof gnikool syawla si tnorF esnefeD arabmA eht esruoc fo dna
.ni deppets ecyoJ dna nepo dils rood ehT
.erutlucirgA fo tnemtrapeD eht rof od dluoc eh tahw gnissucsid ot no devom dah ecyoJ
.daeha sevom nezod a egufretbus fo emag a gniyalp saw ro
.enog dah yeht sa raf sa s'taht tub
".diap llew neeb ev'uoY
,ssenteews ruos fo lluf plup dellif-dees a gnitriuqs ,deppop neht dna denettalf ti
".shtnom wef a tsuj ni gninnur dna pu eb dluohs letoh retawrednu eht ,seY"
.deb eht no lewot sih dessot aneyh ehT ".ti
;rebas labrev sih deidaer ihsoM
"?gnineve ecin a evah uoy did
.draoB eht otno stcejorP dleifneerG fo rotceriD eht gnitteg ot yaw eht evap lliw ti ,yllacitsimitpO"
.oc.edoyak etisbew sih no
",evitnecni erom emos reffo nac I ,spahreP"
rytram a meht ekam dluoc noihsaf siht ni flodnaL gnivomeR"
.netaenu ylegral og dluow taht yruxul fo yalpsid lufetsaw yletarebiled a lla saw siht taht raelc ti edam setalp dehcuotnu fo kcats ehT
.daeh sih denilcni dna ,drawrof srae sih tpek
".ytilibained elbisualp tcejorP eht dna tceferP eht gnivig elihw flodnaL hctapsid dna etacol ot em rof ysae ylevitaler eb dluow tI"
.lortnoc egamad saw tfel saw taht llA
.woleb epacsdnal krad eht ta wodniw eht tuo kool ot denrut eH
"?melborp fo dnik tahW"
.namuh saw eno fi
.dnuora mih edarap ot detnaw ecyoJ dna sthguoht nwo sih htiw enola moor sih ni yats ot detnaw ihsoM
fo erutplucs etarobale na saw eceipretnec ehT
.su esoppo ohw esoht fo tnemtaert eht ni
,hguone tnatropmi tog noitisop sih fI
.wol erew sekats eht ,hguoht thginoT
.daeh reh gninrut tuohtiw wol derepsihw dna mra sih dehcuot ecyoJ
.eceip lufesu erom hcum a ot detomorp teg noos yrev dluow dna draob eht fo dne eht gnihcaer saw nwap siH
.elbmag suoregnad a saw tahT
.nosrep a hcus htiw gnilaed rof snoitpo wef a s'erehT
.stnelat rehto s'aneyh eht ni tseretni on dah ihsoM
.erutuf eht ni ecnailpmoc sih erusne ot desu eb dluoc taht loot rehtona sa dna
,deilper eh ,noisserpxe sih no dloh thgit a htiW
"?etilop erom elttil a gnieb deirt reve uoy evaH"
.tnecs ym pu gnirevoc dna tsaeb gnicnad fo trap eht gniyalp fo deriT .citoxe
,rytram a meht gnikam naht rehtaR
.ni saw eh dleifelttab eht nettogrof dah eh ,moderob sih nI
.sdiar tsetal eht gnitanidrooc neeb sah flodnaL sa nwonk redael tsirorret a taht em llet nwoD arabmA ni secruos yM"
.sedart lla fo flow a ,traH ydrA yb uoy rof daer
emag reh yalp ot esohc eH
-klis etihw ni depparw namow denniks-krad a-
.lavomer tnecs no tneps eb ot gniog si devas I gnihtynA"
”.gnihtyreve niur ot gniog era stsicamerpus-namuh denmad esehT
.gninetsil tpek eh tub ,srovalf hcir eht ni flesmih esol ot ysae neeb evah dluow tI
.noitcartsid sih deciton evah ot demees eno on ,yletanutroF
.nrecnoc reh derevoc reenev gnikcom reH
.deilper ihsoM ",hguone eciN"
iras derediorbme-fael a rof dedart saw esuolb neerg s’ecyoJ
.sserd neerg aes eht ni eno eht si aerdnA"
.ydob dehtolcnu ,tew sih tsniaga looc yltnasaelp saw wodniw ehT
.noitatnemgua sih rof htiw krow ot reisae saw sgod detniap elam fo ymotana dna ,stcnitsni ,sciteneg ehT
—etalp tressed gnivirra sih no desucof dna feiler fo hgis latnem a tuo tel god detniap ehT
-elbat daeh eht ta snamuh eht fo eno sa moor eht no llef ylwols ecneliS
—eugnot sih ssorca dedilg ti sa yrrehs eht fo rovalf eht derovas dna deppis ihsoM
"?uoy ekil gnihtemos ekam ot rehtob neve sremialC‘ eht dluow yhW
ecirp sih eb dluow niaga tijaB gnieeS
.stius dlog dna der ni stnedor erew sreilemmos eht dna
.pihsnoinapmoc erom elttil a evah ot ecin eb dluow ti dna
pu meht eltsert ot ysae saw ti nehT
.niuqennam a htiw gnicnef ekil saw tI .derongi ro
".niaga mih ees ot ekil d'I"
",melborp ruoy s'tahW"
,ecafrus eht morf doof no ecnedneped s'ytic gnitaolf eht neviG
.tifeneb s'ecyoJ rof deddon eH
,evitceffe dna lufrewop eb dluoc ti
.daeh sih fo bob thgils a htiw
.ylrae oot raf dekcip eparg eniw a
enO raeY - tcejorP noitamalceR ehT ni sraeppa ”ekaL nedraG kraD“ yrots sihT
;ssalg eht revo swalc decrofnier nobrac sih nar ihsoM
,ylpaehc os thguob eb dluoc ronoh sih thguoht ehs taht mih derehtob tI
.rekaeps eht sdrawot denrut enoyreve sa htolc fo gniltsur tniaf eht saw draeh saw taht lla dna dednuos emihc A
srehcaop nwod gnitnuh noissim tsal s'ihsoM gnibircsed saw ecyoJ
.ereht ylla na eb ylniatrec dluow nnampleH
.detlusni eb dluohs I"
,tcejorP noitamalceR eht fo draob eht no srebmem ,retal setalp owt dna eniw fo sessalg eerhT
.rageniv dna lio evilo ,reppep
.gniyfsitas erom hcum os neeb evah dluow teltnuag laer A
”,sthgir egavlas“ dah ohw revo tnakilA dna ,anelakaV ,sorypmE hgiH neewteb stcilfnoc eht fo gnitnuocer dehcuoc-yletilop
.secirp doof gnisaercni eht ffo gnitiforp elpoep eht ot eye dnilb a gninrut s'ehs ,won thgiR
.flesmih deraperp eh neht dna derettum eh ",ni emoC"
.stnatsissa s'alegnA fo eno
.nolem fo secils dna ,seirreb detrossa ,elppaenip
.won sraey xis rof esu noitcudorp ni neeb sah flesti egaugnal eht dna desaeler tog tsuj tpircSneerG rof seirarbil tnempoleved noitacilppa ruO
.stnemtraped rehto eht fo noitnetta eht ot mih thguorb dah ti dna snoissim lufsseccus erom sih fo eno saw tI
"?meht rof dellik uoy evah ynam woh tsuj dnA"
,ereh snamuh eht fo tsom oT
.rehto hcae fo noitingocer ni delims htob yehT
gnireenigne citeneg fo sdleif eht ni ecnanimod 'stcejorP dleifneerG eht ffo wohs ot tuo thguorb ytisoiruc nekot a
.seert fo dnats a ni neddih yrrol ria rieht gnidnif retfa noissim ysae na neeb dah tI
.erutlucirgA fo yraterceS eht rof ecin gnihtemos gniod tsuj naht tseuqer siht dniheb erom saw erehT ".stnempihs
.noitareggaxe fo tib a naht erom saw thguoht eh tahw htiw evreserp efildliw a ni gnitnuh
.kaeps ot reh etivni dna kcab pets dluoc eh rO
.stnempihs doof gnidiar neeb sah flodnaL deman tsirorret A .lausu ehT"
.nwod gnirats dna srae sih gnidlof ,dias tijaB
.suoiruc tsuj saw I ,yrroS"
,meht ot nwonk eman sih dna draoB eht no stcejorP dleifneerG htiW
”.tcejorP noitamalceR dnarg eht ot
,nwod tib eh nehW
.riah kcalb fo kcol a kcab dehsurb ehs
!hO" ".elam si ihsoM"
.semulov ekops ,gniyas t'nsaw dneirf remrof sih tahW
,yks eht ni wol saw nus ehT
.retaw fo sessalg gnihserfer ,dloc htiw sessalg eniw decalper sretiaw tnelis ylraen eht ,tuohguorhT
".tijaB" .dias eh ",seY"
,snoisiced nwo sih gnikam fo noisulli eht dah eh ,eugolaid a gniniatretne yb tub
.siht ekil segatrohs esuac ton ot stseretni tseb s'enoyreve ni s'ti dnatsrednu ot gnilliw eb thgim ehs ,melborp tnerruc reh evlos ew fi ,tuB
,ti tsniaga kcab sih denael eH
.moor eht fo dne eht ta yawllah etercsid a morf emit a ta owt setalp deirrac sretiaw eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
".deppots stnempihs doof no sdiar tsirorret eseht ees ot ekil dluow tnemtraped ym ,lleW"
,ylevol tsuj si sserd s'yraterceS ehT"
sgniht rehto ot dnim yrotaderp sih denrut god detniap ehT
",ti ni nettirw yleritne si erawmrif eroc s'ihsoM
,htgnerts fo noitisop a morF
.syad rof ylsselerit meht deklats t'ndah eH
,traH ydrA yb daeR
.atruk laet ynihs a ni depparw namuh denniks-eznorb a fo ezag eht thguac eh litnu moor eht dnuora yaw sih edam eh nehT
.elzzum sih otni eparg a decalp dna
.stnempihs doof no sdiar neeb s'ereht emit tsrif eht t'nsi sihT"
.elims thgirb a htiw pu dekool dna muidop eht no dapeton latigid a delttes ehS
,htrow s'ti tahw rof dnA"
tresed eht fo snoitcaf suoirav eht dezilibatsed sah natorH iebiasT drolraw eht fo htaed ehT
,thguoht eh ,hcum elttil a demees stnemhsillebme dlog rieht dna snmuloc elbram ehT
.ti hguorht delbmum dna etib a koot eH ".sreffo
.yrots eritne eht dlot gnieb t'nsaw eh taht snoicipsus sih dah ihsoM ".siht
",ihsoM htiw yltcerid klat ot uoy rof tseb eb dluow ti spahreP"
.seitilibissop fo rebmun a sah ylnepo flodnaL gnirutpaC
.ylper ni deddon dna aet sih dehserfer ihsoM
.meht ni gnitseretni gnihtyna dah reven yeht dna erofeb sehceeps eseht fo nezod a draeh d'eH
,yltnesba dias ihsoM
.elzzum sih otni ti deppop dna ,ffo eceip llams a erot
"?lasoporp ruo ni detseretni eb dluow aerdnA kniht uoy oD"
.mih ot citamotua saw dedeen eh egaugnal ydob eht fo tsom taht lufpleh saw tI
,og ot mih redro ylpmis dna ytirohtua reh no nael ot reh rof ysae eb dluow tI
"?krow ym ni edirp ekat I ebyaM"
detnaw rehto eht tahw wenk htob yehT
,retal sdnedivid yap dluow won detamitserednu gnieb tub
".hcnets siht yb derehtob t'nsi eson evitisnes ruoy desirprus m'I"
.ton saw klat llams tsuj eb ot deraeppa tahW
.sdrac eht lla dleh eh taht
.elims citsimitpo ,llams a htiw ecyoJ sdrawot denrut eH
.reh morf ssorca esuolb elprup delffur a ni namow denniks-elap ,niht eht htiw senot wol ni gniklat saw ecyoJ ,mih ediseB
.enola saw eh mih dlot rood eht fo ssih tniaf eht ylnO
.deffins ehS ".eniF"
,ssalg eht tsniaga liat sih dekcahw ihsoM "?uoy oD"
.liat sih dih taht atruk klis der derediorbme-dlog htgnel-eenk a erow ihsoM elihw
.evisnepxe oot era sreidlos citenrebyc ,yletanutrofnu
,tlas fo gnisserd elpmis a htiw delzzird
.edisa meht dehsup eh tub ,gnineve eht nekrad ot denetaerht sthguoht esohT
.yawyna meht fo eno eb llew sa thgim I
,eugnot sih tib ihsoM
ssalg eniw latsyrc s'god detniap eht otni engapmahc deruop esuom kcalb gnilims A
.noitats wol fo tseug a sa elor sih otni gnippord
.elzzum sih gniffuts llor teews eht morf deyarps gnici dna sbmurc
arabmA ni egatrohs doof a si erehT"
.suoegrog saw wodniw eht tuo weiv eht ,thgil gninrom eht nI .yenoh dna
,yas dluohs I ebyam ro
muh eht gnittel
"?ecalp ym ta teem ew llahS
"?revlis fo seceip ytriht rieht rof klof derruf rehto llik taht klof derruf naem uoY"
.tneserp eht ot noitnetta sih denruter ihsoM
.thguoht dah eh sa yrartibra sa neeb ton dah gnitaes riehT
.taorht sih ni pmul eht tsap wollaws ot dah god detniap ehT "?aneyh ehT
.llah gninid etarobale eht otni hcra nedoow detplucs a hguorht ecyoJ dna ihsoM dediug tius etihw dna kcalb elpmis a ni tnadnetta nA
.ecneulfni na tub tessa na tsuj eb regnol on dluow eH
",ihsoM ,eno ddo na er'uoY"  2 fo 1 traP
.seye sih dniheb ecnegilletni yrotaderp ,prahs eht was ehs sa ylthgils esor sworbeye reH
,deviecer llew demees tI"
,emoh denruter ylefas erew yeht nehw tlef dah seilimaf rieht feiler eht dna devas dah eh sevil esohw srehcaop eht derebmemer eH
"?siht morf gnitteg ew era tahW
.devirra doof eht erofeb sdap wap sih epiw dna swalc sih morf eudiser evilo eht evomer ot lewot pmad eht gnisu ,meht derorrim ihsoM
.stcejorP dleifneerG ni skrow elcnu ruoy llacer I sA"
.htiw krow ot mih rof hguone saw ti ,llitS
,dias tijaB "?retsam ruoy
tsurht a tnemetats hcae
?su tifeneb siht seod woh ,oS .lufthgileD"
.deb eht no kcab tas dna dehgis aneyh ehT
".hcum uoy tsoc t'ndid eh dnA"
!sgniht lla fo drazzilb a ot eud sniatnuom eht ni maet yevrus a tsol eW"
.sedart lla fo flow a
.roivaheb doog ’stsirorret eht tsniaga egatsoh a meht ekam dna flodnaL nosirpmi nac uoy
.dessap eh snoitasrevnoc suoirav eht no deppordsevae eh sa trela dna drawrof srae sih tpek eH
,nnampleH rotceriD evitucexE dellatsni-ylwen s’nwoD arabmA gnidulcni
,decnef yeht noitasrevnoc tnasaelp eht rednU
.ytsedom sih peek ot sgel sih dessorc dna pu dekrep ihsoM
.gnihctaw eb lliw elpoep
;ecnedive ni syart gnivres on erew erehT
nmad a evig t'nseod ohw enoemos revo
.draeh eh egdelwonkca ot rae na dekcilf god detniap ehT ".sserd
,stnemeveihca s'tcejorP eht gnitnuocer ,ruoh na flah ylraen rof no deggard hceeps ehT
,llor eht deleepnu ihsoM "?won tuoba gniklat uoy era tihs yeknom fo dnik tahW"
.arabmA fo elpoep doog eht rof nrecnoc ruo fo htped eht dna straeh ruo fo ssendoog eht fo tuo siht gniod ton er'eW
—retal setunim neetfiF
.gnidloh erew yeht sdrac tahw wonk rehto eht gnittel tuohtiw noitamrofni tcartxe ot gniyrt hcae
ytiroirp pot s'erutlucirgA fo tnemtrapeD eht saw tnempihs doof no sdiar tsirorret tnecer ehT
.lavorppa laiciffo teg ew erofeb ecalp ni uoy teg ot tnaw I"
.emit eht lla ecaf tnasaelp a no tup ot evah I
".srieht fo yregavas dna ruf taht lla htiw ezeerf t'ndluow serutaerc tsaeb esoht kniht d'uoY
,tsilanoitasrevnoc elbirret a dna evisarba neeb dah aneyh depirts ehT
.aet fo puc gnimaets a flesmih ruop ot desuap aneyh depirts ehT ".revoekat
.dehcterts ecneliS
.der llud dewolg senigne ytivargitna s'anelakaV fo syarra tsav eht ,swodniw eht evoba elbisiv ylerab tsuJ
”ekaL nedraG kraD“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.tuo deklaw yltnelis ecyoJ neht dna deddon ihsoM
,og dluow noitasrevnoc eht erehw gnitapicitna dna sevitom s'rehto hcae gniguag erew yehT .yrrap a ro
",gniyfirroh s'tahT"
.reh ot kcab noitnetta eht gniward ,dias ecyoJ
?ariK rotceriD htiw ssenisub taht…“ "?kniht uoy t'nod
,tsaot A“ .dias ehs
"?elip eht rof ydob rehtona si deen ew lla dnA"
"?ecivres fo eb I yam woH"
,yletilop elims ot esohc ehs daetsni tub
.truoc sih ni kcab llab eht gnittup
,sekansretaW eht sa hcus spuorg denedlobme dna
.ecruos rieht naht rehtar sdrow sih ot erom elttil a tsuj netsil thgim ehs dna ytirailimaf fo tib a reh eviG
—no delbmum tijaB .aneyh depirts eht ot noitnetta sih denrut dna dehgis eh nehT
.tniop eht ot yltcerid erom emoc ot tseuqer sih detpecca dna elims sih denruter ehS
.ylimaf gnitisiv tsuj ,hO"
.em tcepser t'nod yeht
sah tnemnosirpmI
.eerf gnah ti tel ot riah reh depparwnu ecyoJ ".ecin saw renniD"
.eniw fo spis luferac htiw tsriht gnitluser sih detas neht
",serutaerc tneitnes lla dna ytinamuh fo erutuf eht ot ,tsaot A"
"?erac uoy od tahW .on kcuF"
.ésoR ytiurf a htiw deriap puc ynit a ni yrruc otatop ymaerc a—
.decnuonorp ssel regna sih
”ekaL nedraG kraD“ fo
—ssenippah sih tuoba erac did ecyoJ ,level emos tA
?yob …taht dekil uoY"
.ssalg eht ni snoitcelfer eht hguorht elbisiv saw senigne ytivargitna eht morf wolg der eht ylnO
.seye reh dniheb no gniog noitaluclac eht was eH
.tfos neeb dah swap sih tub
.ezeens ot tnaw mih edam emufrep dna engoloc fo xim gniretaw eye eht dna
".gnipom dnuora klaw uoy tey dna snamuh ruoy htiw ereh pu efil derepmap a evil uoY"
elbaronoh dna tsuj era ew woh fo elpmaxe cilbup a eb dluoc yehT
devirra esruoc puos ehT
".ereh loohcs ot tnew dna pu werg I
.yvarg moorhsum a htiw deppot ecir nworb no spit feeb fo lwob wollahs a nwod tes hateehc a dna etalp sih koot raugaj A
.emoctuo eht egnahc ot elttil od dna mih rof secneuqesnoc citsard evah dluow lasufeR
dna ecuttel yhcnurc fo dalas a saw esruoc tsrif ehT
.ti fo erawanu yletelpmoc saw tnenoppo sih dna now dah eH
.moor sih ot denruter ihsoM dna ecyoJ ,rennid retfA
.doof eht fo ecnellecxe eht rebmemer ot gniog saw eh
.deganam dah esle eno on yaw a ni ssenilenol tnatsnoc tsomla s'god detniap eht gnisae
.dekcilf srae s'god detniap ehT ".thgin
kaeps ot nrut s'ecyoJ saw tI
.pal sih no ti delttes dna erawrevlis sih dnuora depparw nikpan dlog eht dellornu ihsoM ,ecyoJ gnirorriM
.elbat eht dekcots evah tsum tsitra na
.tseretni etilop htiw detiaw anyaR ".nosrep
,yldica dias ihsoM
",gnineve ym tuoba ksa ot ereh nwod emoc tsuj t'ndid uoy ,lleW"
.sraey wef a ni licnuoc yrosivda na no flesmih dnif dluoc eh
# # # .derepsihw aneyh depirts eht
.ksam sih hguorht deelb ssenilenol sih tel dna
.mih fo tnorf ni daerbtalf dna sevilo fo etalp etihw ynit a decalp raugaj demoorg-yletalucammi na elihw
.skaeuqs hgih ni tuo emac eciov s'god detniap ehT ".ot
—nairatilage ylbakramer saw tcejorP noitamalceR eht ,ecafrus eht nO
srae sih denrut rood eht morf emihc A
.cipot neergreve na saw erutlucirga
,noisserpxe sih deleets
.yawa ti gnihsaw eniw eht fo noitasnes eht neht dna
".detcepxe dah I naht uoy ot erom s'erehT"
.on ,yletanutrofnU"
.sruoy morf tnereffid taht lla t'nsi ereh ecalp yM"
.dengief yleritne t'nsaw tseretni siH
.ylluferac sdrow txen sih esohc ihsoM
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
—ylthgils daeh reh deppit ecyoJ
"?ris ,etalp rehtona ekil uoy dluoW"
.htiw pu nworg dah snamuh eht htiw nommoc saw taht noihsaf a ni wap a delriwt eH .prahs saw ehS
.eye eht ni reh dekool god detniap ehT ".draoB
"!lufthgiled woh hO" ".ma'am od I"
.ylper t'ndid ihsoM ".gnihctaw
tnereffid erew ereh snopaew ehT
"?arabmA ot nwod daeh neht dna gninrom worromot yromra eht ni drahciR teem uoy naC
.rehto eht htiw tsiaw sih dnuora lewot eht dna wap eno ni llor teews a gnidloh ,dias tijaB
.eerga dluow I kniht I ,esac siht nI"
".ruc deppihw a dnif I daetsni tub
.denediw seye sih dna tnemom tsefeirb eht rof ezorf nahtaN
.raey tsal eht ni ssergorp tnellecxe edam ev'eW"
,dalas eht gnihsinif emit sih koot eH
-daeh sih detlit ihsoM ".ylimaf
meht htaeneb delwarps sniatnuom derevoc-duolc fo egde eht no dnalmraf neerg tsaV
.ylthgils daeh reh koohs dna dettut ecyoJ
.deunitnoc eh ,sthguoht reh fo erusnU
.daeh sih ton tub
.delaes saw etaf s'flodnaL ,taht htiw dnA ".sekat
,yppahnu yletarepsed os er'uoy fI"
.dias erew taht sdrow eht tsuj naht erom raf detacinummoc noitasrevnoc tceridni nA
.ti rof krow uoy nehw gnirepmap ton s'tI"
.sdrow sih dniheb niap eht edih t'ndid ti tub ,tfos tsomla
aet ytpme na ,sbmurc dleh ylno mih ot txen yart eht dna oga emit gnol a deird dah ruf siH
.reh fo tuo noitamrofni erom ward ot yrt dna sselgninaem gnihtemos ta noitasrevnoc eht tniop dluoc eH
,daeherof sih neht
,neve saw ylper siH
# # # "?raew ot em ekil uoy dluow tahw ,oS"
.elzzum sih ot ti deirrac dna swalc sih htiw ylitniad elppaenip fo eceip a dekcip god detniap ehT
.emag eht tuo hsulf ot emit
.tneced eb ot gniog t'nsaw eh fi derevoc eb tsael sa dluow eh os pal sih revo lewot dedracsid a deggard eH
".sdworc gnidaer ta doog yldrah m'I tub
.seitilicaf eht esu ot sevlesmeht desucxe snamuh eht fo emos ,revo hceeps eht htiW