,tohs eht ekat ot dah eh
.ylimaf s'flow denam eht tisiv dna nruter ot yaw a dnif dluow eh taht flesmih desimorp god detniap ehT
.ti nips ot deirt yeht woh rettam on
.esu uoy eno hcae rof mrof a tuo llif ot gniog er'uoy dna ,sdnuor PA 5 uoy teg nac I"
.elims ediw a htiw dias ycreP
?setamssalc reh ti saW
,ylhguoroht nwod mih dettap tibbar eht dna deddon ihsoM ".snopaew
—anelakaV rof rennid elpmis a saw tI
.ti detcepsni dna nopaew eht detpecca ihsoM
.yawa llaf ydob sih tlef god detniap eht dna deppots traeh siH
.gnihtyreve eb dluow egaugnal ydoB
.gniliec dna sllaw eht derevoc eulb elap fo sedahs lareves ni tniap dna
.woleb raf skcor dna
,sgniht lufesu rehto wef a dna ,noitinumma
,nepo neeb dah tekram eht fI
.suorehcaert gnitoof kcils ydaerla eht edam ssom secalp emos nI
.efas ot kcab rotceles s'elfir eht gnikcilc erofeb htaerb deggar a koot god detniap eht dna
.ydob sih hguorht doolb dehsup taebtraeh ralugnis ,tnatsid A
.eert elpam a fo edahs eht rednu elbat a ta tas dah yeht dna diap ihsoM
.regnol yna gnitiaw ni tniop oN
,setius ralimis ni nees dah eh noitaroced hsival eht naht rehtaR
.uoy htiw klat ot tnaw d'ehs tbuod I" ".esimorp I
.ecnetnes-dim gnihctiws semitemos ,uoy truh sa
,degats tlef gniteem elohw sihT
.setalp derevocnu won eht morf esor amora eht sa seson rieht dellif nrocreppep fo tnecs prahs ehT
.senot tfos yllauqe ni deilper dna rae na denrut ihsoM
.egalfuomac sih no denrut dna elfir sih pu dekcap eh sa
"?emit siht ereh uoy sgnirb tahW"
.niorg sih kcehc ot
,pu emac nus eht erofeb ,ylraE
.flesmih deppots tub dehgis tsomla eH
.ria eht dellif sevaw fo dnuos eht dna ssom dna tlas fo tnecs eht ,ylwolS
roolf eht derevoc teprac ydrutS
.daeh s'xnyl eht no delttes sriahssorc eht sa revresbo tnatsid a ylno saw eH
,slotsip nuts fo skcar ,edisnI
.pu kcab demraw yeht sa meht otni debbats seldeen dna snip ,erofeb emit yreve dah yeht sA
,mih ot gnihtyna yas uoy erofeb dnA
,atad hguone htiW
,tnemom a rof ,tuB
.tinu knat ria na no tluassa latnorf a rof uoy gnippiuqe ekil diputs gnihtemos od ot gniog ton m'I tub ,ihsoM ,em ot nos a ekil er'uoY"
ot gnulc ihsoM taht trofmoc llams taht saw tI
.nwoD arabmA revo dellor mrots eht erofeb anekalaV ot denruter god detniap ehT
.rae na debbur ihsoM ".emit
.sgel s'klof derruf tsetuots eht neve derettahs evah dluow llaf a deldnah ylisae ydob decrofnier siH
.sremialC‘ eht ,sey hO"
.keehc s'drahciR tsniaga elzzum sih detser eh dna edis eht ot deyalps srae s'ihsoM ".eno
.gnilriws pots ot dniw eht rof detiaw margorp eht ,ytinrete na roF
.ni edih ot tnemtrapa despalloc-flah a etacol ot ysae saw tI
.luos deniats ydaerla na no niats erom eno dna htaed s'rehtom eno ta paehc neeb dah ecirp eht dna
.won yb srotanimulli detnuom-waj sih morf thgil derarfni eht nees evah dluow enord ehT
.llaw kcab eht raen swodahs eht ni gnittis mih ees ot elba eb dluow eno oN
.tniop a dah drahciR esuaceb yllatnem dehgis god detniap ehT ".tuo
.egalfuomac sih detavitca
.evila flodnaL gnikat rof yap ot gnilliw meht fo wef a s'ereht taht dnuof I ,dnuora gniksa retfA
.ylbatrofmocnu dias ihsoM ",did I"
—esiwrehto ro lacinahcem
.ecnelis ni —ylwols eta yehT
.eciohc rehto on dah eh
.gnihtyna eb ro gnihtyna od ot deen on
,deraeppa DUH tabmoc ehT
;flesmih koohs god detniap ehT
.tsehc s'aneyh depirts a otni
.moordeb eht ot deriter yeht ,raelc erew setalp eht retfA
,god.ecioveht ta
",ksat elbatterger A"
.ereh m'I yhw ton s'taht tuB"
.noissim eht tog esle enoemos fi eid dluoc elpoep rehto fo tol a
,gnippiks saw rethguad s'flodnaL .detatiseh eh
,drawrof deklaw dna
.deb eht no nwod yal eh dna roolf eht no tnew gnihtyrevE
mih ot txen dehtolcnu nwod tas tijaB sa detfihs hcuoc ehT
,skcor revo dehsarc sevaw sa ,dna
,tsap rieht nevig seimene rettib neeb evah dluohs ycreP dna eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.feirb saw ecyoJ ot egassem siH
,dnammoc latnem a htiw
.desitsahc yletairporppa kool ot kcab srae sih dennip ihsoM ".tnasaelpnu
.taht dias evah t'ndluohs I ,yrroS"
.dnah eht no wap sih detser ihsoM ".kcab
.evah dluohs yeht naht erom wenk syawla yehT
,efil reh ekat ot eno eht neeb dah eh esuaceb dnA
.rethgual fo lwoy a htiw mih desirprus xnyl ehT ".evila
.erehwyreve saw neerG
.noisiv lamron ot revo kcab seye gnihca sih dehctiws dna ,hteet sih dettirg
.emitemos rethguad dna efiw ruoy teem ot ekil d'I
.sredluohs sih no thgiew dael eguh a ekil tlef enizagam sti ni strad PA evif eht dna swap sih ni yvaeh saw
,noacyL edoyaK yb
wap reh fo kcab eht gnisu gnidulcni
.peed os t'nsaw taht eno
.deredduhs god detniap eht dna
.spuc yalc owt htiw topaet nori gnimaets a dna sriahc dehctamsim xis htiw elbat doow a saw ereht ,edisnI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ereh nwod devil taht sdrib eht htiw gnola gnignis traeh sih tlef ihsoM dna
.dnoyeb srats eht dna nwoD arabmA ees ot elba neeb evah dluow eh
,laer dellems ti ,eson s'god detniap eht oT
.senizagam ezis-lluf owt otni strad NDNG sih fo lla dedaol dna
.ytic eht fo egde eht ot syawllah railimafnu hguorht tijaB dewollof neht dna esirprus ni deknilb ihsoM "?tnemtrapa weN"
.decitonnu og ot sdneirf owt neewteb gniteem a rof ecalp laedi na ti edam ylflesmaD eht ta dworc tnatsnoc ehT
"?sey gniyas terger ot gniog I mA"
.rehtegot wodniw eht tuo derats yeht sa ekops meht fo rehtien ,emit gnol a roF
,yretsulb saw gninrom txen ehT  .peels sselmaerd
,reppiz eht no dellup dna flesmih deleets eh ,ffilc a ffo gnipmuj ekiL
.pirg eht dnuora delruc wap sih nehw weiv otni deppop DUH tabmoc ehT
.snoitpo eht ekil t'nod ew fi nevE
,letoh sih ta kcaB
.lacitpeks dekool tijaB ".nees
,spets erom wef a retfA
.noisiv sih fo egde eht ni dih taht smargorp eht fo lla desolc dna ffo kcab gnihtyreve denrut eh nehT
.reh gnizylana trats ti dah dna margorp rotceted eil sih pu dellup eh ,enola lliks no yler naht rehtaR
.tcirtsid retuo eht ni euneva niam eht nwod senil tcefrepmi ni detuops seert
.reggirt eht nwod dleh eh sa ecaps ynit eht hguorht dednuos skcarc detautcnup ,wolS
,yllacitamotua detixe margorp noitanissassa ehT
.taht ot deifitset dednal eh erehw morf raf ton noteleks enilef A
,htap sti fo dne rehto eht tA
.mra sih ot wap a gnihcuot
.snoitar grobyc derovalf "yrrehc" dna redwop gniksam tnecs ekil
erif elgnis ot efas morf revel rotceles s'elfir eht dekcilf eH
.sedanerg rof drahciR deksa evah dluohs eH
.ruf rieht delffur dah ezeerb dloc a fi sa saw tI
.sgel ruoy neewteb liat ruoy htiw ereh evael uoy erofeb ereh er'uoy yhw em llet uoy t'nod yhW
.deksa neve saw ti erofeb rewsna eht wenk eh tuB
.elbat eht ta taes a koot dna flesmih koohs yllatnem god detniap ehT
.eruliaf sih no gnitnemmoc saw rood eht fi sa
.gnol flah a dna retem a revo saw lerrab lluf eht dna
.mih ot txen ydob derruf ,mraw eht tsniaga denael dna deffins god detniap ehT
.rehto hcae ta elbat eht ssorca dekool yeht sa dedaf ylwols rethgual ehT ".uoy dessim ev'I"
.niaga uoy ees ot gnitcepxe t'nsaw I"
,reggirt eht llup t'ndid eh fI
.gninrom taht was eh
,tcirtsid noitamalceR eht morf arabmA dlO gnitarapes ecnef eht was eh nehW
,resolc tog eh nehW
.lenap latem nrot a dnuora morf deraeppa klats eye der dna sgel kcalb ynihs fo riap A
".dehsdoolb diova ot ees nac I yaw ylno eht s'ti tub siht uoy gniksa etah I"
,tnemom gnol a retfA
.setalp demmir dlog no srevoc revlis dna
tatibah elbanoitseuq eht
.rethgual rieht ro tnecs rieht yrrac t'nod srettel dna serutciP
,neppah ot gniog t'nsaw
.kcab gnippets erofeb tnemom a rof daeh s'god detniap eht fo kcab eht dnuora dnah sih depsalc drahciR ".snoitpo
.gnihtemos mih dlot tahT
.ecneloiv evissecxe saw esnefed tseb eht
.ffilc ykcor dna ytic fo stib nellaf otni dehsarc woleb retaw eht elihw latem gnitsur dna ,retaw aes ytlas
.eulb thgindim peed a ot demmid sthgil gniliec eht
.thguoht god detniap eht ,emahs a saw tI
.eye sih fo renroc eht ni deknilb ecyoJ morf egassem a nehw gniraeppasid saw thgil fo yar tsal ehT
uoy pleh ot ylekil sa tsuj erew taht senord anihcaM elbatsnu otni gninnur fo ksir eht syawla saw ereht ,peed sihT
.ydob sih otni kcab llef eh sa srae sih dehcaer pop tfos A
ni erif fo etar eht ,oslA
"?ssenisub siht ,oS"
.arabmA fo ytic gnitaolf eht fo slevel rewol eht neeb dah tahw fo egakcerw detsiwt eht hguorht tuc erew detsixe taht shtap wef eht ,ereh nwoD
,gnihtyna gnidnif tuohtiw dehsinif ehs nehW
.enibrac a sa ti esu ot noisnetxe lerrab eht evomer dluoc eh
"?elihw a ni ecno tisiv laicos a ekam ot truh ti dluoW"
;edam ydaerla saw noisiced ehT
,feiler etinifni s'ihsoM ot dnA
.esle enoyna ot siht nwohs reven ev'I"
,no desab saw ti nugliar eht naht elbailer erom saw tI
.sriahc deffuts fo riap a neewteb elbat dne dna flehskoob a htiw rolrap llams a ot mih del tibbar ehT
".ssenisub etanutrofnU .ssenisuB"
.oga sraey dah yeht noitasrevnoc a gnirebmemer ,dias flow denam eht ",thgiR"
,emoh dedaeh flow denam eht nehT
.troper txen yb ezilartuen lliW
.tuo emac romra yvaeh ni tibbar ylrub a dna denepo rood ehT .deilper eh
.ti od ydob sih ekam llits dluoc erawtfos
,reggirt eht llup t'ndid eh fI
.noitciderp s'enord anihcaM eht dellacer eh ,ylisaenU
,tsurc nrocreppep a htiw kaets erar toh
,snoitseuq erom ynam esiar dluow rewsna eht
,noonretfa ynnus a saw ti
daeh s'flodnaL no dekcol margorp ehT
etalp roolf a rednu neddih enibrac sih tfel eH
,scitilop on saw ereht emit siht tub sllah gninid eht morf laem yna sa tnellecxe sa saw tI
,rood eht no rorrim eht ta gnikooL
# # # .daetsni kcapdem lanretni sih pu dellup eh os
.sedart lla fo flow a
.yas ot gnihtemos dah oot yeht fi sa noziroh eht no demool sduolc krad tub
.dnoces rep sdnuor eerht-
.nwod top ytpme eht tes dna spuc rieht fo htob dellifer flow denam ehT
.deppots dna lanimret tropsnart eht fo tuo deppets eH
fo enizagam trohs dna lerrab dednetxe eht tfel eH
?mih ekil ,gninrael evol tsuj ehs did rO ?srehcaet ehT
.htaenrednu luos eht hcaer ot yaw a dnuof dna sllaw tliub ylluferac s'ihsoM fo lla tsap nees dah eH
.aet fo puc a flesmih deruop dna dehgual god detniap ehT ".hctib
.dleifelttab sih saw sihT
.mih rof gnitiaw eb ot enoyna detcepxe t'ndah eH
.tiaw ot emit evah t'ndid eh tub
.gnilaeppa ton saw ssenkrad eht ni dnilb gnieb fo tcepsorp eht tub
.ecyoJ htiw snoitasrevnoc sih ekil
.niaga tcerroc neeb dah enord anihcaM eht
.puc gnimaets a mih thguorb ,sgnikram ralimis htiw ,xnyl eganeet A
.stnalp neerg dna senot htrae htiw ylpmis desserd saw eno siht
.noitseuq ykahs a deksa neht dna eniw sih fo pis a koot ihsoM   ".taht
morf flow detniap suoiragerg a
.reh morf ssorca tis ot mih detivni ehS
.dnuorg eht no elbaliava gnihtyreve tuoba tsuj htiw sllats fo lluf tekram gnilwarps a tsap
.devlovni gnirevuenam lacitilop eht nialpxe ot gniyrt naht retteb hcum noissim sih fo ecnatropmi eht deyevnoc eil a tub
.yrt ll'I tub tluaf ruoy toN" ".yrros m'I"
.noitisop otni elfir eht evom ot nageb smra sih dna
eno suoiverp sih naht regral semit eerht ylisae deb a ot txen elip a ni sehtolc sih tfel ihsoM
,dna elfir sih pu dekcip eH
-wol yllufniap saw
.pu dekool ihsoM ”.noitseuq enO“
,snoitatcepxe sih ot yrartnoC
,snerraW eht fo trap tsekrad ,tsepeed eht ni ,ereh nevE
.ssenrah ytivargitna na tuohtiw ssecca dluoc namuh yna tniop tsewol eht saw anelekaV no kced noitavresbo ehT
.reggirt eht no detatiseh regnif sih tub
.detcepxe dah eh naht recin hcum saw roiretni ehT ".edisni emoc uoy erofeb teef ruoy epiW" ,dias ehs
.ereh eb t’ndluow I
”.stsirorret tuoba skniht ehs tahw itavagruD tceferP ksa uoy t’nod yhw
.peels sih morf ekow ihsoM
.niarg suoiruxul sti tsniaga swap sih fo sdap yrehtael eht dehsurb eh dna
.flow denam deroloc-tsur a saw sriahc eht fo eno nI
.gnibrutsid meht fo lla
.ecnelis eht gnikaerb ,dias aneyh eht
,gniyl detah ihsoM ".diar
,detrats aneyh eht
.ynapmoc s'aneyh eht rof yap ot ecirp llams a saw taht tub
.noissim siht rof nopaew laedi na saw 6-RG a ,syaw fo tol a nI
.aet neerg tnellecxe na saw tI
,yppols oot ro denifer oot saw eh fI
.regnif gnissim sih fo buts eht gnibbur
.ti tuoba eb s'teL .lleW"
"?gniod uoy era woH
gab eht ni sdnuor PA
.ta eb ll'I egnar tahw wonk t'nod I dna noissim noitanissassa na s'tI"
.elzzum gninrub a dna seye gnizeerf fo tsoc lufniap eht ta emac ti
.mih no erifkcab dluoc noitasrevnoc eritne siht
.delims ehs sa gnihton dias xnyl ehT ".ereh
.lufetarg eb d'I ,flodnaL dna em neewteb gniteem a pu tes dluoc uoy fI .doolb oN"
kcab gnidloh deppots eh nehT ".esle
.tnasaelpnu dna krad erehwemos aedi taht ffutS
,noisiv derarfni sih gnisol ksir ot gnilliw saw eh fi krow thgim egalfuomac siH
.puc nwo reh gnitfil ,deksa xnyl eht
.tnemetatsrednu na neeb dah tnemtrapa weN .nepo dils ti
,mih ta dennirg dna pu tog ehS ".taht od ll'I"
.sdnah htob htiw wap s'god detniap eht koohs dna ylrednet dias nam eht ",ihsoM"
# # # ".25:70 ta etelpmoc noissiM" .esicerp dna
.taeh ydob nwo sih fo
.ylrettib dekaeuqs god detniap ehT
.ti evoba dehcrep ylflesmad eulb a htiw ngis gnignah a rednu delgnim klof derruf dna snamuH
.neppah ot tuoba saw tahw ot suoivilbo ,eerferac
,gniht gnorw eht yltcaxe gniyas rof tnelat gnizama na dah tijaB
.hgih oot tsuj saw tsoc ehT .t'ndluoc eh tub
.sraet kcab dleh ihsoM sa
".ereht thgir yatS"
.ecalp thgir eht ni saw eh wenk eh
—efil fo ngis tsal eht saw taht ,yletanutroF
.enilef a morf leef yllamron dluow eno tahw dnoyeb ecnelis eht ot leef yrotaderp a saw erehT
.wap sih debbur ycreP
ot doolb sih dellihc yldipar niks citenrebyc
.noitpo tseb eht ylbaborp saw tib a gnihcnilF
,srewot nekorb dna detsiwt morf gnuh seniv gnilwarC
.oihO tsewhtuos fo
,noitasrevnoc ta tpmetta on edam tijaB
.dnuorg eht ot deppord flodnaL
.ytic eht fo sniur eht dnuora gnilwarc rof etairporppa stnap dna trihs a no dellup dna 6-RG sih dedaol eH
.derepsihw aneyh eht
.ti wollem ot deirt taht gge dna ,torrac
.egamad laretalloc fo muminim a dna
.yromra s'tcejorP dleifneerG fo tnemtrapeD eht ta drahciR teem ot tnew ihsoM ,gninrom eht nI  2 fo 2 traP ,noacyL édoyaK yb
.elims a htiw dias ehs ",llew sa eniM"
.reverof tsal dluoc traeh sih ni htmraw eht dehsiw dna seye sih desolc eH
.erif citamotua ot revo ti dekcilc dna
,tenalPruF yb enO raeY
,lerrab htgnel-lluf sti htiw ,elfir ehT
.rebas latnem sih tuo dellup dna riahc eht otni kcab delttes eH
.elims das a mih evag tijaB  .cirbaf elprup degnirf fo tnuoma tserab eht ylno ni dehtolc
.ekops ehs sa gnitcaer saw ydob reh woh no daer elbanosaer a mih evig ot elba eb dluow ti
"?gnineve enif siht snerraW ehT ni gniod ew era tahW .ihsoM"
.eman sih dias eciov cinortcele na
.enord eht no eye eno tpek dna noitcerid taht ni deppets ihsoM
.pu gnitteg tuohtiw elbat eht ssorca morf wap s'god detniap eht koohs eH
gnireffus yrassecennu on neeb dah ereht
.dekaeuqs eciov s'god detniap ehT
trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
,dnuos taht ot ytilanif a saw erehT
.wollip a degguh eH
,deunitnoc ihsoM ",llew yreV"
,peed rehtona otni flesmih detades dna deb dloc eht no enola nwod yal eh os
retaw elbisiv ylerab dewohs yeht litnu denekrad swodniw eht nehT
"?gnihtemos uoy wohs I naC"
.eniw fo ssalg a mih dednah dna
# # # .ssenkrad eht otni ffo deppils dna terger ni srae sih deppilf god detniap ehT
pihsredael s'tcejorP eht gnitanissassa ta tpmetta na ekam ot noitinumma hguone mih gnivig dna
.rioN toniP etirovaf sih eb ot tuo denrut eniw ehT
,dias flow denam eht
.troper tnatculer s'dneirf sih derebmemer osla eH
.noissim sih ot nruter ot emit saw ti nehT
,noitatnemgua sih htiw detargetni epocs tliub-motsuc eht dna
.romra thgil etartenep dluow strad cisab neve ,llitS
.mih naht retsaf evom dluoc fo wenk eh sepyt enord eht fo tsoM
.uoy knaht dnA" .dias ihsoM
.deksa eh "?rethguad ruoY"
,etius yruxul llams a saw edisnI
redluohs sih tsniaga ti dellup eh sa gnitrofmoc saw thgiew s'6-RG ehT
.knis traeh sih tlef dna pu ti dellup eH
"?tnaw uoy od tahW"
.ytic eht gnitcetorp llawaes eht tsniaga gnikaerb sevaw eht dna egrus mrots a fo retaw gnisir eht ta wodniw eht tuo derats ihsoM ".troper
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,lamron ot denruter dah seye sih ecnO
.dah reve dah aneyh eht laem tseb eht eb ot dah siht hguoht neve
.spahreP .hguorht gnissap tsuJ"
.taes a gnikat ,deksa ihsoM
.sepytotorp dleifneerg fo flehs eht ffo elfir a dellup dna dias drahciR
?reggirt eht llup ot eno eht eb ot evah eh did yhW
"?ylimaf ruoy si woh
,yrelec fo xim eht derewoprevo taht htorb nekcihc ycips a dna seldoon taehw lufrovalf kciht fo etsat eht derebmemer yldiviv eH
",flodnaL htiw teem ot ereh m'I"  .dias eciov eht
.surtic fo tnih lufthgiled a htiw rettib dna gnorts
,deraeppasid ti ,sdrow gnitrap elbatrofmocnu esoht htiW ".worromot
.mia sih rewol t'ndid tub gnirif deppots god detniap ehT
.niar eht yb yawa dehsaw gnieb won saw taht dnuorg eht no deloop doolb eht fo thguoht dna eniw der fo retnaced eht ta derats eH
.niar gnisnaelc a ekil mih revo revolc teews dna tlas naeco dehsaw taht ezeerb remmus toh a otni tuo deppets ihsoM ,dnuorg eht otno delttes tropsnart eht retfA
.diar tsal eht tuoba deuqip etiuq s'ehs dna flesym erutlucirgA fo yraterceS eht htiw deklat I
,retal sruoH .gnitiaw
".enim fo etirovaf a si ereh ekal ehT .gnihserfeR"
.nosrep tsenoh dna elpmis a saw flow denam eht tub
.emit gnikam fo rettam a ton s'tI"
,egde eht no nwod tas ihsoM
.mih rof tuo dial dah ehs trap eht yalp ot deunitnoc eH
,wonk ot dedeen eh fI“
.daed flodnaL tnaw sremialC‘ ehT"
,aet dehsinif-flah sih ta nwod gnikool ,dias eh ",yrroS"
.etilop ylgnideecxe saw ehs
",NDNG fo dnasuoht wef a dna
.nwod puc nwo reh gnittes ,deilper xnyl redlo eht ",seY"
",lufituaeb si sihT"
dloc saw ecyoJ ot egassem siH
.rae nrot a htiw xnyl elamef a yb deipucco ydaerla saw sriahc eht fo enO
.daed saw rae nrot a htiw xnyl ehT
,od dluoc eh gnihton saw erehT
.ylper t'ndid dna aet sih ta derats ihsoM "?drawretfa dnA"
,mih rof gnitiaw aneyh depirts a saw erehT
.dedausrep ylisae os eb ot gniog t'nsaw ehs raelc ti edam daeh s'xnyl eht fo ekahs llams A  .desserp eh
,traH ydrA yb daeR
.sthguoht sih htiw enola eb ot evah t'ndid eh taht mih dednimer redluohs sih no wap eltneg a nehT
.dediar gnitteg peek taht syovnoc doof eht tuoba tespu etiuq era sremialC‘ ehT
.lortnoc pu evag dna nottub etucexe eht tih ihsoM nehT
.keew tsal secivres ta uoy dessim eW"
,ereh emit tsrif sih t'nsaw tI
.ecaparac kcalb s'enord redips eht ffo degnip yeht sa skraps fo srewohs sselesu ni edolpxe ot rodirroc eht nwod welf strad nezod a ,sdnoces ruof nI
.draytruoc eht deretne ,rae nrot a htiw rehtom reh dna ,xnyl gnuoy a
.ecnatsid eht ni llaw a no gninihs sthgil thgirb was eh ,aera gniteem eht ot esolc tog eh sA
.eye sih fo renroc eht ni dehsalf margorp sisylana ehT
.tuo meht decrof eh sa mih elgnarts ot denetaerht sdrow siH
.yerp reh saw eh ekil tsomla saw tI
".gniteem eht ta flodnaL mrah ot gnihton od ot esimorp I"
snoitcelfer elap eht naht thgil retteb edivorp ot no denrut waj sih otni tliub srotanimulli eht dna derarfni ot noisiv sih dehctiws eH
,raeh dluoc eh dnuos yreve
.krow lennosrep-itna egnar-esolc naht dnoyeb gnihtyna ta llew yrev krow t'nseod ffuts NDNG eht ;omma PA egnar gnoL" .deksa drahciR "?esle gnihtynA"
"?noos emityna gnola eb lliw eh esoppus t'nod I
",aet doog si sihT"
.mih ta dewang noitseuq enO
.erusaert reverof dluow eh seiromem evah dluow eh
",yats ot em tnaw t'nod uoy fI"
.ti dniheb xof der eht fo tnecs eht ksam ot hguone gnorts saw taht sreppep dna htorb fo amora na htiw trac eldoon a ot yaw eht del dah flow denam ehT
.moor eht ni erutaef gnitseretni tsom eht emaceb ylneddus spucaet gnimaets eht dna depoord srae riehT
,llems dluoc eh tnecs yreve gnidrocer ruoh eritne na tneps eH .ytuaeb gnitnuah
.ti ot kcab mih dewollof rood eht ta mih tem dah taht tibbar emas ehT ".tuo
.semag gniyalp ot desu saw ehS
.rewot deniur a fo pot eht ot neesnu debmilc ihsoM
seye sih tpek eh elihw daeh sih ffo ylesool gnuh srae siH
.thgirb ylevisserppo dna daehrevo hgih saw nus remmus ehT
;emoh etuor tnereffid a ekat ot gniog saw eh dediced dna enibrac sih defas eH .ypeerc saw tI
.taeh neddus eht rof etasnepmoc
.devorppa noitanimreT" ,trohs saw tI
.noitseuq a neeb dah reve ereht taht ton
.siht ekil birc a teg ot ereht nwod gib gnihtemos enod evah tsuM"
.gnilttes ytic eht fo snaorg lanoisacco eht dna latem tsniaga gnippird
.yllufecarg tixe ot saw tfel saw taht llA
.dnuorgrednu klof derruf eht ot noitcennoc yramirp sih
.meht raeh t'ndluoc eh tub gnimaercs klof derruf ees dluoc eH
.eciov sih ni trofmocsid fo tnih a htiw deksa ihsoM
.ylper t'ndid god detniap ehT
.redrocer sih morf yromem a pu dellup dna seye sih desolc eh daetsnI
.drawrof mih denoitom ehs dna tnecs sih thguac ehs sa dehctiwt eson reH
.latnemitnes gnitteg eb ot emit eht ton saw sihT
,seiranecrem rehto eht fo wef a htiw gniklat saw I"
.ria eht ni niar fo llems eht dna daehrevo yks krad a htiw
.tniop sih ot deunitnoc neht dna dias eh
.loohcS kraP tseW fo tnorf ni draytruoc eht no ni demooz yllacipocselet
"?6-RG a em evig uoy naC
".elihw a ni ecno emit ekam t'nac uoy ysub os ton er'uoy yleruS"
,reggirt eht llup t'ndluoc eh fI
# # # ".taht tbuod reveN .lliw I"
.elzzum sih deppat ycreP ".ees I"
.nopaew tcefrep a t'nsaw tI
,ycreP htiw gniteem sih dehsinif eh retfa dnuora rednaw dluoc eH
wolg on saw erehT
reffo ot dah tcejorP eht snopaew tseb eht fo emos htiw nissassa derruf a gnimrA
.retaw eht revo delgnad sgel sih elihw ees dluoc eh thgis yreve dna ,ruf sih tsniaga ezeerb yreve
".tnemtrapa wen ruoy ni su rof gnitiaw eb dluohs renniD
ecnatsid eht ni dehsalf gninthgil tnaillirB
sessalg eniw latsyrc htiw sgnittes ecalp owt erew moor nommoc eht ni elbat nedoow devrac eht no dnA
.sedanerg yvaeh fo reilodnab a dna
.loohcs devol syawla dah eh
,elbisivni yltcefrep tsomla saw eH
.hcaorppa sih edih ot tpmetta on gnikam
,won ees dluoc eh elihW
.yppup em esuma ot deganam uoY" .thgirb seye
.ni dellor sevaw eht sa traeh sih ta dewalc ssenilenol dna
".dnim ym no tol a dah ev'I"
,elpmis a dnif dluoc eno
.anelakaV no yats tsal ym gnirud sromur emos draeh I"
.ria eht ni kaerts etihw a tfel trad PA ehT
.dnoyeb aes naeco tilnoom eht dna
,elfir sih saw edisnI
—tnew sluos reverehw ot
.der denrut riahssorc eht dna
# # # .yawa klaw s'ruoh na flah tsuj saw flodnaL
thguoht eh noitarepo eht fo trap tsrow eht saw siht ,tbuod a tuohtiW
!thgif a tuohtiw pu flesmih evig tsuj ot flodnaL teg nac uoy kniht uoy dnA"
.dengised saw ti sa tsuj ,ylisae rehtegot deppans elfir ehT
.taht mih llet ot margorp retupmoc a ro anihcaM xaP dedeen eh taht ton
,euneva niam eht nwod deklaw eH
.ereh tfel eht ekaT .tsew raf oot er'uoy ,ekaL nedraG kraD rof gnikool er'uoy fI
.egalfuomac sih esu ot etal oot saw ti dna resolc tog sdnuos gniparcs ehT
.deifitnedi flodnaL"
.rehtona neht dnA
.draobssehc lacitilop eht no gninoitisop retteb teg ot llA
—enog saw luos reh dna niarb reh ni serutcurts lativ eht hguorht nrot dah trad ehT
.snaeb neerg demaets dna
:mih thguat dah drahciR tahw wollof dna enibrac sih ydaer ot dediced eh ,dne eht nI
".ti od ot evah I tuB"
.tuo dnuof eh nehw staorht ruo htob tuc dluow rotceriD ehT
,krow egnar esolc roF
,esnopser ni dna moor eht gnillortnoc retupmoc eht ot ti tnes dnammoc elgnis A
"?ehs si ,regnif a tsuj rof elttes ot gniog t'nsi yraterceS sihT"
.ekil dekool ehs tahw wonk ot dedeen llits eh ,flodnaL erutpac ot noissimrep teg t'ndid eh fi nevE
.reh tog uoy enicidem eht ot sknaht ,llew gniod si rethguad yM"
.ynoclab kced noitavresbo na fo sniamer eht no deppots eh ,ekaL nedraG kraD fo edis nretsae eht nO
.gnippam etarucca rof no deiler ti sprihc cinosartlu eht ekam t'ndid eh fi krow t'ndluow ylbaborp dna latnemirepxe saw ti tpecxe
,tsehc s'flodnaL no senil der eht delttes dna redluohs sih ot pu elfir eht dellup eH .emit saw tI
,ragus dna maerc htiw hcir aet ro eeffoc decips ylivaeh derreferp hcum evah dluow eh
strad gnicreip-romra reporp fo enizagam lluf a tuohtiw ereh nwod gnimoc t'nsaw eh ,emit txen dnA
.sliar eht fo noitidnoc eht dekcehc eh sa deilper ihsoM
.gniwonk ton ffo retteb saw eh dediced eh neht
,elbaeganam erom saw ti ,enibrac a sA
".elbisnopser flodnaL redisnoc yehT
.ylkciuq oot evom t'ndid eh sa gnol sa
",egassem a gnola ssap nac I tub ton s'eH"
,nwod sthgilf eviF
,ma I" ".llew kool uoY"
,hguone llew thguof eh fi ebyaM
.swodniw gniliec-ot-roolf decaf taht hcuoc rehtael laer a otno nwod flesmih desae dna
,noissim sih fo emoctuo eht rettam oN
.hteet fo lluf elims a htiw dias ehs ",gnisirprus toN"
"?aet fo puc a ekil uoy dluoW"
.teem ot deerga dah flodnaL
,ylnmelos dias dna redluohs s'god detniap eht no dnah sih tup drahciR ".uoy
”ekaL nedraG kraD“ yrots sihT
.elam saw flodnaL taht noitpmussa tcerrocni sih ot noitcaer on saw erehT .dias xnyl eht
.kraP tseW ni loohcs ot seog rethguad reh ,spleh ti fI
.tuoba yrrow ot sgniht etaidemmi erom dah eh
.sredluohs sih dnuora depparw mra s'tijaB
.eye eht ni dneirf sih dekool dna dehgis ihsoM
.moor letoh sih morf thgil gnidaf eht ni retaw eht revo tuo dekool ihsoM ,retal syad owT
.uoy htiw og t'now xnyl eht tub gniteem ruoy htiw kcul dooG"
.worros teiuq ni decarbme dna rehtegot pu doots htob yehT
”?wonk nnampleH seoD“
.yppup remialC‘ elttil trams a er'uoy nehT" ".on ,lleW"
,tnorf mrots gnirewot eht rof neeb t'ndah ti fI
—flodnaL saw xnyl eht taht tbuod elttil tfel margorp rotceted eil sih morf sisylana dna gnidrocer ehT
.meht dniheb morf sraet pu demmug dloc eht evomer ot sdileye sih debbur eh sa
mih ediseb esle enoemos tuohtiw dloc erew steehs ehT
,gniwehc teiuq dnoyeb esion on
.dnuorg eht tih dah ehs erofeb
.rood latem yvaeh a dnuora strop nug evisurtbonu lareves dna saremac dethgilhgih stnalpmi sih
,emarf eht no nottub eht fo hcuot a htiW
".ereh eb t'ndluow I ,dluoc I fI"
,dnuos gnikohc a neht dna gnihtaerb rieht fo dnuos eht ylno saw ereht ,tnemom a roF
.rolrap a dna smoordeb owt htiw
.senigne s'anelakaV morf noitarbiv on dna
.snerraW eht otni denepo rood tneb a
.eno teg dluoc ohw enoemos dnif ylbaborp dluoc eh
",ti fo tuo meht klat nac uoy esoppus t'nod I"
",krow taht ekam ll'I"
.deppolf srae sih dna flesmih koohs eH
—eniw hcnerF fo elttob dlo seirutnec a dnif t'ndluoc ylbaborp eh elihW
,sselluos dna derucinam saw anelakaV sa ereh dliw sa saw tI
wodniw eht fo noitcelfer eht ni eniltuo sih fo wodahs eht was ylno eh
".yawa teg ot em rof tluciffid s'tI"
.redips deromra-etisopmoc eht ot kcab sih evael dluow taht noitcerid a ni detniop gel kcalb A  ".ereh
.nees reve ev'I gniht lufituaeb tsom ehT"
;pu dekrep srae siH
.evila reh ees dluow ehs emit tsal eht eb dluow siht gniwonk ton
".tsehc sih ni efink a kcits klof derruf eht fo eno evah ot yenom fo tol a gniyap si enoemos dna
",NDNG fo sdnuor 002 naht erom on dnA
.gniteem rieht fo esoprup eht ot yletaidemmi tnew dna deddon ycreP ".rethgual
.tseb ta elbanoitseuq saw stcejorP dleifneerG fo tnemtrapeD eht htiw erutuf sih
.flodnaL htiw teem ot emac I ,mu ,lleW"
.loohcs eht otni sriats eht pu tort xnyl deganeet eht dehctaw eH
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
—rovalf s'aet eht yojne ot tnemom a koot ihsoM
;reh htiw pihsnik a tlef eH
,gniylf saw ti nehw emas eht neeb dah arabmA fi erus t'nsaw eH
"?efink ruoy thguorb uoy esoppus t'nod I"
”.tniop ruoy ees I“
,roolf tpews-dniw eht revo derevoh riahssorc yarg A
.worromot trats sessalC
.nabrut elprup a gniraew nam denniks-krad a saw lla ti fo elddim eht ni dnA
.ylteiuq deksa ycreP
- tcejorP noitamalceR ehT ni sraeppa
.tfel eht ot dna sriats eht pu saw devreser dah eh moor gniteem etavirp ehT
.sucof dedeen hcum mih thguorb dna noitades fo gof eht yawa koot tnalumits dlim A
.gnihtyna gnidloh t'nsaw eh wohs ot swap sih detfil dna ezorf ihsoM
.mih dniheb tuhs degnalc rood yvaeh eht ,tuo deppets eh retfA
.delkcarc rood eht ediseb rekaeps eht
.tuo uoy wohs lliw aralC dna aet ruoy hsiniF
.saw eh elbatceted woh fo etamitse na dewohs srab neerg gnitaolf ,trohs fo tes a dna ,detceles stats elfir sih htiw
.kcab emoc uoy ees ot tnaw I .efas eB"
.hctib a s'ehs ,llew ,efiw yM
”ekaL nedraG kraD“ fo
.eno tluciffid a eb ot gniog si noissim siht tub ,llew neeb ev'I"
.rennam elbatrofmocnu tsom eht ni delkcuhc eciov ehT .deilper eh ",dnim t'nod uoy fi ,hguorht gnissap tsuJ"  .25:90 daer noisiv sih fo renroc eht ni kcolc ehT
.yawa klaw ot denrut rehtom reh dna edisni tnew rethguad eht erofeb tsap tnew staebtraeh lareveS
.thguoht ihsoM ,yppup eht ot tnioP ".sgel
.emit yreve yawa htaerb sih koot nwoD arabmA
.ecaps llaw eht fo lla tsomla pu koot sreworht guls dna ,selfir trad
.neht yakO" ".yats esaelP"
.mih ot txen deb eht no ti tes dna kcapkcab sih pu dekcip god detniap ehT
.eciohc sah syawla enO"
.sedart lla fo flow a ,traH ydrA yb uoy rof daer
,peels ot resolc mih gnirb ot hguone t'nerew deirc eh sraet ehT
retaw tneserp-reve eht naht rehto dnuos elttil yrev saw erehT
.tlah mih edam latem tsniaga latem fo psar a nehT
",siht od t'ndluow I ,uoy t'nsaw ti fI
.nwod raf siht elbisiv thgil on saw erehT
.sremialC‘ eht htiw snoitcennoc wef a evah I"
.desu gnieb saw eh woh ezilaer t'ndluow ycreP depoh eH
.deremmats eh ",ev'I"
”ekaL nedraG kraD“   yojne esaelP
.latem no latem fo psar thgils htiw eht ot gninetsil
.taes rehto eht koot dna srevoc etalp eht devomer tijaB
.arabmA ot nwod sdaeh eh erofeb yromra eht ni ihsoM nioj won eW .flodnaL tsirorret dellac-os eht ezilartuen ot noissim a nevig saw ihsoM ,emit tsaL  .oc.edoyak etisbew sih no seirots s’édoyaK fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
",teiuq neeb ev'uoY"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
"?deen ll'uoy kniht uoy od tahW
.margorp noitanissassa sih pu dellup dna ffo regnif sih koot eH
.leef t'ndid eh ssensuovren wohs ot yletarebiled dewollaws ihsoM ".hcnub
sih sa ruf sih fo tuo dezoo aet gniliob sa toh taews dna denrub srae siH
—saw ”hcnerF“ a revetahw
.eb dluow ydob sti fo klub eht erehw no sriahssorc der eht delttes dna htaerb sih dleh ihsoM
,margorp noitacolohce na evah did eH
.rood nedoow a ta deppots yeht ,nwod slevel lareveS
.gnirewsna erofeb aet sih deppal ihsoM
,thguoht ihsoM ,siht otni noitaraperp fo tol a tup dah enoemoS
.worbeye desiar a htiw deksa tijaB "?ti si tahW"
.snopaew rof uoy kcehc ot deen I ,ezigolopa I"
,noacyL édoyaK yb
.sevaw eht fo stserc etihw eht thgilhgih ot thgil hguone tsuj dehs ssom eht fo wolg eulb mid eht
# # # .ecneF eht fo edis rehto eht no letoh sih rof tfel god detniap eht dna
.ecnerefer erutuf rof redneg s'flodnaL yawa delif ihsoM dna nworf a htiw dias ycreP
.ylmrif dias drahciR
.rewop gnippots dna egnar fo esnepxe eht ta tub
"?klaw ruoy saw woH"
.gninoitisop retteb morf noitpo lahtel-non a etaitogen dna evila ni flodnaL ekat dluoc eh
.spil sih desrup drahciR ".krow
,PA 002 tsael tA"  "?hcum woH"
".em rof deksa uoy dias ecyoJ tuB
.neeb evah dluohs regnif tsellams s'ti erehw buts detacnurt a dah taht wap eht no deregnil seye s'ihsoM
.rewot deniur ybraen a otni kcuns dna letoh sih fo tuo deppils god detniap eht nehT
,ekaL nedraG kraD revo tuo gnikooL
trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.enozo eht llems tsomla dluoc eh dna
,eulc yna saw roivaheb gnilttesnu s’enord sti fI
.hguorht emac eh nehw wen gnihtemos syawla saw ereht tub
.egnar retemolik-net s'nopaew eht fo esu lluf ekam ot mih gniwolla
,rewsna sih wenk ihsoM tub ,meht neewteb dias saw gnihtoN
?em morf tnaw uoy od tahw ,oS"
,dias dah drahciR tahw etipsed dnA
.spets tcatni fo tes tsrif eht otno pord retem-ruof a ot hguorht ezeeuqs ot mih rof hguone ediw tsuj saw yawriats dehsurc ehT
.tuoedih a naht emoh a ekil erom hcum tlef tI
,rehtom reh ot eybdoog devaw ehs ,sriats eht fo pot eht tA
",shtnom ni uoy nees t'nevah I"
,egalfuomac sih gnisU
.ksam reh pord ot reh nettog dah tca siH
.gninrom taht tekram eht ni ycreP tem dah eH
ylrettib tpew god detniap a
.kcordeb tih yeht erofeb snerraW ehT ni og dluoc eno sa peed sa saw siht tub
.seye das htiw pu dekool ycreP ,enog saw aet eht nehW
.riahc elbatrofmoc eht ni tas dna reffo eht detpecca ihsoM
”ekaL nedraG kraD“ fo
.hcnub evitisnes a eb nac yehT
.gnihton dias tub rae na dekcilf god detniap ehT ".siht
,yvaeh saw elfir ehT
,htaed s’flodnaL morf niag dluow anihcaM xaP tahw derednow eh tnemom a roF
.loop ot nageb doolb ,ylwols ,nehT
.aet gnippal seugnot rieht yb nekorb ylno ,ecnelis ni knard yehT
.efil s'nosrep eno dne ot dedeen saw taht lla saw taht ,sdrow owT ".devorppa
.klat ot tsuJ .snerraW eht ni erehwemoS
,ssom yhtrae fo stnecs eht ni ekat ot ylpeed delahni eh
,yramesor dna rettub htiw seotatop dehsams
",yltcerid mih ot kaeps ot ekil yllaer dluow I"
”.devlovni teg elpoep rehto fi tsaf yllaer yssem teg dluoc sihT“ .dias eh
.noitpo na t'nsaw dnuora gnioG
" .swap ym no doolb evah t'now I tub ,tol a uoy ewo I