,ecnelis nekorbnu ,eiree fo etunim rehtona retfA
.mailliW ot erom ecno dekool remrof eht
,sthgis sih pu denil mailliW
,eoR drahciR eno fo noisneherppa eht roF
,delf dna derettiks swodahs prahs-efinK
,pu deretnac noskcaJ moT
denrael eb ot nossel A
noitcifonex yraretil fo noissucsid ot detoved yliramirp ,tseW lanidraC
.ynapmoc railucep a saw srieht ,ssenriaf
,erob flesmih eh ecarg eltbus emas eht htiw derrits kaolc nosmirc siH
.flesmih ot derettum eh
.tseretnisid rettu no gniredrob ecarg diugnal a htiw sgnidnuorrus sih deyevrus
,detfihs ecnanetnuoc sih ,ekops eh sA
.enolerT rotcoD deralced
,noom eht fo gnignahc eht dna sevael eht fo gninrut eht ma I“
detniauqca ydaerla flesmih seveileb ohw nam a
.tdrahnieR dna tnemelC srongisnoM yb
.nevahs naelc ecaf enipluv ,prahs sih
,srengierof eht ta ecnalg evitruf a tohs eh ,reppepluC droL ot revo gnigdurt retfA
,daehA	 .derewsnanu ti tfel eH
,erom ecno delims eH ”.hsirep ro ,tpada
,no elbmuts thgim eno tahw wonk tonnac enO
.nus gnisir eht morf erif fo revils a thguac kcab sih ssorca gnuls elfir eht ,denrut eh sA
.rekirts erif a deveirter dna kcap sih hguorht degammur eh
emiT	 .tiaw ot dengiser dna
.esproc eht tcepsni ot detnuomsid dah ohw
”.ecneserp ruoy yarteb lliw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.rehtohcae htiw ssenisub nwo rieht evah ot meht esoppus ot elbanosaer si ti ,stnediser sah ssenkrad eht fi dnA
,repeed a htiw xim smrofinu fo der dirolf eht dehctaw dna ,ekoms dna hsa tsdima stenoyab fo tnilg eht nees dah eH
…erom rednu niaga teem yam ew epoh od I“
sA	 .enots ot sbmil sih tes thgis ehT
s’tdrahnieR	 .eciffus ot epoh ton dluoc ti wenk mailliW
.seye neerg gnicreip sih dehcaer reven elims eht
,iksaL rimisaC yb
.ni denioj dah slacol eht fo lareves ,dehsinif eh emit eht
s’erehT“	 .ecno ta nam eht ot ekilsid a nekat dah
,iksaL rimisaC yb
.meht pots ot sselrewop tfel saw eh elihw
,maol neddos eht evoba gnirevoH
”,dallab suoicipsua tsom A“
nevE	 .mih fo daeha secap erem etteuohlis s’tdrahnieR tuo ekam yldrah dluoc seye sih ,stoob rieht fo daert eht htaeneb gnihsols dna gnihsiuqs dnuorg eht ,seert eht hguorht gniklats fo setunim lareves retfA
.tseretni yrotaderp htiw eldniwd dna rekcilf semalf eht gnihctaw
,derettug sehcrot eht ,ria eht morf deniard htmraw gniniamer eht sA
.slotsip ro selfir detfeh srehto elihw
A“	 .derettum namstnuh eht
moolg gnin’peed eht ni retnuocnE thgim uoy ecnahc yb ,eve eno ,fi dnA
,dranyeR em deman yeht eniarroL
.dias latnenitnoc eht
”.noitseuq tneicserp tsom a si
,sdnah gnikcarw s’mailliW ni efil ot derekcilf erif ynit
.noziroh eht detserc nus lirpA gniredloms eht sa neve
.sdrow eht dootsrednu t’ndah mailliW
,meht fo eno sa tub
.murd raw a ekil gniremmah traeh sih ,erah a sa kciuq rehtaeh eht otni delbmarcs eh ,htaerb rof gnipsaG
yrassecen demeed sa htiw tlaed eb ot ,ecitsuj morf evitiguf
.nood yaw ynnac a s’ti ,ynnih ,dniM“
.traeh sih deppirg llihc repeed a sa neve
setats namreG eht fo eno spahrep ro
.decnuonna eh ”,thgil ot nward eb lliw yrrauq
,god a fo evitcepsrep eht morf dlot
lled ’na room re’o diar ’na evaer oT      llef morf nood emoc
tseretni evisnep neewteb erehwemos detser yllauteprep ecnanetnuoc siH
…eltit relpmis a yb em dellac ecno evals keerG A
.noisneherppa sih tsdima pu elbbub ot noitsuahxe dna iunne gniwolla
,deremmats mailliW ”-
.goD fo tsohG ehT
.htuoy fo dessessop oot lla tey dna
.gnihsilbuP sirneF morf elbaliava won si
,tsrif eht denioj neht dnah rehto siH
,tnemelC rongisnoM ,tsrif
,eciov sih ni revauq eht desruc mailliW
edahs A tsaf uoy spirg taht dnah yci nA mool swodahs erehw yrc sseldrow A
,emit tsrif eht rof ton ,thguoht eH
ruO“ .revo gnidirts ,deilper tdrahnieR
htiw llits uoy sekirts dnA
”,ydob sih nopu kram a ton
,sehcrot kcurts nem eht fo lareveS
”.remmef ton s’eh fi ,rooM ybkriK pahyaM
.enola emoc ton dah tseirp eht
.sretsnom fo kaeps ot nageb nem eht ,wol seciov riehT
:wal tneicna tsom s’erutan yb ediba I ,siht nI
,dnalekaL eht ni ereh deregnil llits rebmevoN fo llihc yerg
tahT“	 .hsurbrednu eht fo swodahs eht ni gnitnilg yrovi
,eugnot evag sdnuoh eht fo eno ,ecnatsid eht nI
,rennid yaddim feirb a gnirud emac etipser ylno ehT
ehT	 .deniamer tdrahnieR ylno
.gninekrad ecaf sih ,kcab denrut neht ,tseirp eht retfa deppets eH
,htworgrednu eht fo krad eht ni ,ereh tey dna—
tdrahnieR	 ”?eman laer s’evitiguf siht wonk neve uoy oD“ .deilper eh
thgin fo kcalb ni sroom eht klaw yehT
.dlrowrednU eht otni tnecsed ’sessylU fo kniht tub pleh ton dluoc mailliW ,nrohtwah eht otni decnavda yeht sA	 ”.raen era
,sdrow s’tdrahnieR no kcab gniknihT
.sduolc yerg kciht fo kaolc a dniheb morf reep ot noom deznorb ,elap eht gnivael ,sllef tnatsid eht woleb knus dah nus eht won yB
,ynobe ekil krad niks sih
,wol a esora taorht sih fo shtped eht morF
,mih erofeb gnileenk latnenitnoc eht dnif ot ekowa
ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,rednuht ni denword hsiugna fo seirc draeh
.deliocer mailliW ,reraen denael eh
”.kcirt revelc a saw
dot ’lo ynnac nehW
,lliw neila emos ot dnuob ,sregnif sih sa dehctaw eh ,gniredduhS
,riah sih ekorts ot tah sih detfil ylfeirb
nI	 .roticilos a rof ecalp on saw siht taht
.edalg eht fo egde eht ta gnivom ssenkrad repeed a saw was eh tsrif
.flesmih rof edalg eht enimaxe ot tnemom a koot neht ,mih retfa derats
.dias tdrahnieR ”,modsiw rof noitidure ekatsim ot sa ssimer os eb reven dluow
A	 .mih mialc diov eht tel ot dengiser eh
”.gniht lufrewop a si ,yornoC retsaM ,eman
.seye neerg gnicreip fo riap a otni gnizag flesmih dnuof mailliW ,retaw luof eht morf gnisiR	 .loop ykrum a otni dehsalps dna toor a no delbmuts eh ,egailof fo sertem lareves hguorht gnignulp retfA
.tsim yb dekaolc dna wodahs ni delppad ,demool nrohtwah dna
.ssyba eht otni gnoldaeh segnulp dna hcrot a sehctef ohw nam eht ni gnikcal
,gnilkcuhc ,tdrahnieR elihw
.stbuod sih gniwollaws flesmih dnuof mailliW ,yltcerid sih tem ezag s’tdrahnieR
,yllacirohpatem ro yllaretil rehtie
esu on eb ll’erans ehT
I“	 .derettum eh
.yrc eht pu koot noos kcap eht fo tser eht dna
.krad eht ni suoituac
evom ton dluoc eh llits tey dna
”…desolc eb ylurt reven nac
A	 .swodahs eht otni kcab gnidlem erofeb tuo gnihcaer
,sehcrot gnivaw ro snopaew gnitsioh erew srehto elihW
fI“	 .nmuloc eht fo daeh eht raen gnidir ,latnenitnoc eht ot ecno ta tnew seye s’mailliW ,tiusrup rieht gnimuser nopu dna
,niks namuh ni sevlesruo kaolc emit ot emit morf yam su fo emos elihw dnA
,dnim sih gnippirg rorret tcejba
,keehc sih ot kcots nedoow looc eht gnisiaR
”!sdal ynnob ,yawoH“ fo tuohs a htiw nid eht gnirewsna
.eciov sih derewol dna ni denael rotcod eht ,ffo gniliarT
.retnac eltneg a ta ffo tes ytrap eht fo tser eht elihw daeha depollag moT dna
.thgilhcrot eht dewollaws ksud sa gnirettacs sesroh dna nem despmilg eh ,fooh a gnigdoD
ehT“	 .erom ecno tuoba decnalg dna thgirpu dereggats eh ,kcum eht morf elfir sih gniveirteR .deksa mailliW
,neeb evah dluohs gel sih erehw pmuts war a htiw rooM a derebmemer eH
,swodahs eht gnoma evom ton did tI
,delriws tsim fo slirdnet
seiceps dairym s’htraE eht denoihsaf dah rotaerC eht hcihw yb sdohtem eht nehw
rewoT nodnoL no dehcram effilcyW dna relyT nehw dna
,htaerb peed a gnikaT
,ezag s’teop a htiw dnal eht ni koot rongisnom dalc-kcalb eht erehW
.riap eht erofeb pu denepo edalg a ,hcaorppa rieht noitseuq ot tuoba saw eh sa
.erudne gnol ton did ti tub
.eno ni sevlow owt
ruO“	 .seye dlareme sih ni gnirekcilf sevael nmutua
.ynohpmys tnadrocsid ni gnilbmert
A“	 .tseirp eht ot ,ylfeirb os reve ,dettilf hcihw—seye s’tdrahnieR dehcaer yllanif elims eht ,siht tA
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.netsil ot deniarts mailliW
.traeh gnicar sih mlac ot tseb sih gniod
,ksud gnirehtag eht otni tuo gniratS
,taorht sih dnuora sregnif fo pirg eht derebmemer eH .nosmirc rehcir
mailliW	 .dloh ot erad dluoc stsaeb rewef neve dna nem wef taht
.sgnul sih morf htaerb eht evord thgis ehT
,gnitnuomsiD	 .ecaf ffilc a raen rehtaeh eht tuoba gnitsac meht gnidnif ,kcap eht emacrevo ytrap eht gnineve yB
,taeh gniretlews eht ni pu gnillew tor fo hcnets eht
,demussa eh ,seirtnuoC woL ehT
,tekcop taoc sih fo shtped eht ni delbmuf
”,meht retfa hctaw lliw rongisnom doog
:gnos ni eciov sih gnisiar dna ytrap eht htiw ni gnillaf
nI“	 .mailliW ot kcab dekool eh
”.noitseuq ym rewsna t’nseod taht“
tuB	 .mailliW thguorb nrut ni dah pihsdroL siH
”naM nahT sgnihT rekraD“ saw sihT
.ekenieR sa em wenk ramieW fo teop dlo eht enihR eht dnoyeb elihw
.enihw tfos a derettu spaleaL
,drofekarD rehsA ,namstnuh dael eht detiaw edis sih
mailliW	  …  .mih deflugne thgindim dnoyeb ssenkcalb A
,epocselet yb dekcart dna detrahc eb dluoc sevlesmeht snevaeh yrev eht nehw ,ega denethgilne siht nI
.gniraelc eht otni decnavda ti sa gnola meht gniggard
”.mih hcuot t’ndid sworc eht nevE“ .deksa rehtona
,esroh sih pota derebmalc noskcaJ moT
.mih deliaf yromem tub
,ecaf sih gnihtab thgilerif
wodahs fo tfihs yreve
,dipet dna keem ,gnikaerb saw nwad sa tsuj esproc eht nopu emac yehT
,ecnis dehcuot neeb ton s’eh tub…“
,htrof deppets tdrahnieR
”.raen ward ew swonk yrrauq
,swodahs eht tsdima deralf seye gninrub owT
,goD fo ecioV ehT no
”?srehto eht tuoba
A	 .dehtaerb sa hcum os nam a toN .devom gnihtoN
fI	 .lopotsaveS fo serohs eht no niur der ot ecaf s’kcassoC eht dehsams eh sa
,seye sih erew gnikirts tsom tuB
,elims luftsiw a dehsalf dna kcab decnalg reppepluC droL
,tsdim rieht ni tas tdrahnieR
.esproc eht ot deddon eh ,taorht sih gniraelC .rehsA
”…tub ,ksud ecnis daed neeb ylekil s’eH“
.ydaer eb dna ,ereh niameR .od lliw
.dnammoc fo dessessop llits tub
sA	 .draeh d’eh selat eht eveileb tsomla dluoc eh
,sdnah gnilbmert sih gniydaets ,nehT
.spetstoof rieht ni dort I
.lwof gnoma xof a ekil ynapmoc eht tsdima tas etaicossa sih
yrots lavivrus citpylacopa-tsop a
yruf dna rorret eht dellacer
,mih dnuora rethgit reve werd swodahs gnipolevne eht sa deduolc htaerb siH
”?dias maiL tahw draeh uoht ,yB“	 .hsilgnE reporp otni tcelaid eidroeG deggur eht trevnoc ot dekrow dnim s’mailliW
,yornoC retsaM ,secnatsmucric suoicipsua
:ytiralc gnikirts htiw won mih ot denruter senil tsrif esohw eno
,floW .J sunaI yb daeR  .noitamina nretsew dna
.htuom sih fo srenroc eht ta gniyalp nirg yls a
,htworgrednu eht fo kcalb eht ni dehcterts dna detfihs
,tsej terces emos ot yvirp erew eh fi sa
”.sworc eht neve toN .tsaeb ro nam yb
,nehT	 .seye gniknilbnu htiw dehctaw tdrahnieR llits dna—
,levon tubed esohw
”,stiwflaH“	 ?noititsrepus ot gnilc llits nem dluoc woh
.ecipicerp eht fo egde eht ot edorts mailliW
,teef sih ot delggurts mailliW	 ”.ylthgil tub ti ffod dna nod ew
nehW	 ”–uoy era tahW“ .deksa mailliW
,eganam dluoc slacol eht fo tsom naht hsilgnE reporp erom ni eman sih nevig dah eH .tdrahnieR
,tnemom a tub rof dna—deppils dah ksam a ekil tsomla
ehT	 .gnol tiaw ot evah ton did
burcS	 .ytrap eht fo tser eht tsdima drawno esroh sih degru mailliW ,tnemom a retfA
si yrots s’thginoT dna
;srobhgien nwo sih dnoyeb kool t’ndeen eh ,sretsnom thguos nam
,seye sih gnisolC	 .eneres
,traped ot edam rettal eht sA
.enips s’mailliW nwod dekans revihs
.gnillewd tilerif a fo htmraw dellaw eht nihtiw morf deyojne nehw dleh ti noitcivnoc dna ecalos eht dekcal ylegnarts egdelwonk taht
”.tooba dehsab ’nitteg esu oN
,yornoC mailliW eno yb
.ssarom ytaep eht otni gniknis ,yerflap sih morf nworht saw mailliW
”naM nahT sgnihT rekraD“
,wodahs dna tsim fo lriws a ,reraen werd ti sA
,floW .J sunaI yb uoy rof daer
traeh sih htiw skcom ohw ,dnal euqitna na morf rellevart A
,decnad yeht sa gnihctaw
.ssenkrad gnidnuorrus eht revo dloh suounet-ydaerla rieht gnirednerrus
.dlrow eht fo secalp peed eht ni llewd
,repsihw a evoba ylerab eciov sih ,dias latnenitnoc eht ”,rebmemer dnA“
.htym ro yrotsih fo tuo tsaeb a neeb evah thgim
”.sgniht selbmurc emit
”,nruter ruo nopu os od llahs
,syawla sa tub—htuom sih fo srenroc eht ta deyalp krims a fo tnih ehT
.tsrif klofsnik ym fo eno retnuocne ton od uoy yarp ylno I“
.redluohs s’mailliW no dnah a psalc ot drawrof deppets neht
thgiliwt yb wodahs a
,swodahs eht morf mih ta dewalc sehcnarb lateleks ,deggaJ
.srae sih dehcaer reven sdrow eht tub
lennahc ebuTuoY eht setarepo osla eH
.mlac gnineve eht derettahs keirhs
.serutangis dna slaes reporp eht lla htiw dexiffa
,traeh sih ta gnipsarg
dlareme gnicreip a
nehW	 ”.dnah sih naht rehtar
.traeh namuh eht fo shtped eht ni deregnil gniruocs htrow swodahs ylno eht
mailliW	 .hcaorppa sti ta knarhs semalf ehT
,dewollof ecnelis etaciled ,dloc A
”.noihsaf a retfa ,klofsnik ym fo enO“
;elah tey riaf saw niks s’nam ehT
,denivid gnieb won neve erew
,resruoc sih pota tas reppepluC droL
.elfir sih fo parts eht rof derebmalc sregnif gnilbmert sa ssenkrad eht gninnacs seye sih ,deldruc doolb s’mailliW
…I naht elbacima ssel raf era meht fo tsom dnif lliw uoY
”,dot kcurtsevol a tub
A	 .dennirg tdrahnieR ,ssenkrad eht
emalf llams a deldnik eh
iksaL rimisaC yb ”naM nahT sgnihT
nam naht sgniht rekrad raf tub
deraor rednuht sa edalg eht decarg thgilyaD .derif
rehsA	 ”?lliW ,he ,syad dlo doog eht ekil tsuJ“
.eugnot ngierof a ni gnirettum dna yrasor a gnihctulc ,ybraen doots tnemelC rongisnoM
,sniev sih hguorht yaw rieht deraes swalc ycI
.yks nretsew gnilkrad eht ssorca gnideelb saw erif s’nus eht fo tsal eht ,woleb sroom eht dehcaer ytrap eht emit eht
,nemstnuh dna sdnuoh fo llim eht tsdimA
sdrahS	 .ecno ta mih ot tnew seye
.edurtni ton thguo eno hcihw otnI
,namygrelc eht tub ,tsipaP a tsurt ot htaol saw mailliW
.namygrelc eht htiw ecnalg gniwonk a degnahcxe neht
.seye dlareme sih dehcaer reven elims
,kaeps mih dehctaw mailliW
ycarcotsira naissurP fo segami derujnoc ytilager mlac s’nam eht—
.snademmahoM eht fo eugnot diuqil eht htiw gnilgnim seirc dehsiugna
,wenk mailliW ,emyhr eht ot erom saw erehT	  raef sseleman
.eram nwo sih pota reve sa ciots tas tnemelC rongisnoM ,edis sih tA
rekraD“   yojne esaelP  .rorroh htiw
.nopaew eht dekcehc dna elfir nwo sih deredluohsnu mailliW
.erudne ot epoh thgim yeht erehw kcor fo sessecer repeed eht ot gniknils
.ezag sih morf yhs tub pleh ton dluoc mailliW
.detcerroc tdrahnieR ”,nexiv
.xof gninnirg a fo egasiv eht despmilg mailliW
eb ot esiw si tI
.noinimod ruoy rednu gnignahc si dlrow eht esuaceB“ .mailliW ot denruter ezag sih dna ,derebos ecnanetnuoc sih tnemom a retfA .ytinmelos dengief htiw deksa eh ”?floW eht nisuoc egavas ym neve yaws sicnarF desselb ton diD“ .tsaerb sih ot dnah a gniward ,nihc sih detfil
,noissapmoc fo remmilg a dleh ezag ruod s’tseirp ehT
,ni-reppihw yltrop eht ,noskcaJ moT elihw
tahT“	 .mailliW no tser ot gnimoc erofeb tseirp eht ot dettilf seye s’tdrahnieR
,wodahs dna krum fo krowhctap a ,sroom deduorhs-tsim yal woleb sertem fo snezoD
airbmuC ni kcap tsenif eht ,sdnuoh sih rof reppepluC droL ot emoc dah tseirp ehT
,spil sih dessap noitseuq eht sa nevE ”?uoy era ohw
degreme ssenkrad eht ni gniht eht sa niks sih delkcirp eci fo
eH	 .yerflap tuntsehc sih edirtsa digir tas
”,sraef s’nem eht gnisae sdrawot yaw gnol a og dluow noitamrofni elttil
.nwonk reve dah eh lla saw retniw fo krad dloc eht litnu
.hself nwo sih tub gnihton dnuof sdnah sih ,denethgit pirg eht sa neve tub ,tnaliassa sih ta dehctulc eh xelfer yB .taorht s’mailliW dnuora denethgit dnah neesnu na
,noitatnemucod reporp eht lla dessessop dah
,lamirp eht htaeneb
.mih edisgnola pu gniward regnarts eht ees ot denrut mailliW ,elddas sih ni gnitratS
,evoba yponac eht hguorht srats eht despmilg eh
nI	 .hctam elgnis a deveirter yeht rehtegot dna
tahW“	 .ssenkrad eht ni gnitnilg seye neerg sih
,krowidnah s’repaeR eht ot regnarts on flesmih ,mailliW
yB	  !’ninnur-a dot ydoolb ’aht
,htrim gnikcom dna
,sdrib noirrac derehtaef-kcalb eht ot dettilf seye s’mailliW
.snigiro sih ta sseug ot mailliW gnivael
mrahc suoronos a deirrac eciov sih hguoht—
mailliW	 .thgin eht otni dehsinav eh ,drow rehtona tuohtiW
,gnihtirw dna gnikohC
,rednu devres dah yornoC tnanetfeL gnuoy a niatpac eht naht won reyerg
”,enim fo ecnatniauqca dlo na …si yrrauq ruO“
,denedaorb nirg siH
”?taht saw tahw
,nrohtwah tsesolc eht morf hcnarb yrd a gnippanS
;erif nmutua fo stnih htiw dehsad tessur a riah ylruc ,trohs sih
.ti fo derepsihw ylerem s’tdrahnieR
.ecnelis gnikcom ni ezag sih erob dna sterces rieht dleh ohw
,dnE tuohtiW retniW
deksa ”?mih yrub ew
tdrahnieR	 ”?su gnidia uoy era yhw …yhw nehT“
,detsujda seye sih emit eht yB
.mih dnuora tuo yalp thgim ti woh ot sa debrutrepnu tub suoiruc
mih erofeb hcnarb delrang a no elfir sih fo elzzum eht depporp eh ,ssom fo hctap a pota gnihcuorC
.ecnelis nmelos ni gnivresbo ,nrohtwah delrang a fo shguob eht ni dehcrep tas sworc lareves ,ybraeN
,htlaew fo detsaob tius s’reppepluC droL
.rehtaef s’kcoc etihw elgnis a htiw denootsef
tsuJ	 .dnim eht gnieerf yludnu fo yaw a dah ssenkrad ehT
…ohW“	 .ecalp s’tsaeb eht ni tdrahnieR dnuof erom ecno dna ,deknilb eH
.tseroF eladezirG ro ,notsinoC ot nood ’niog eb ll’eh nokcer“ ,delbmurg mih ediseb nam redlo na
ehT	 .ria hsilgnE psirc eht erom ecno dehtaerb eh ,gniredduhS
,noinapmoc sih htiw sdrow ydnab naht rehtaR
,yornoC retsaM ,taht won …eman a ot sA“
yB	 .taoc a gninnod sa yllarutan sa emac snoitom eht ,edaced a ylraen retfa nevE
thguaN“	 .dehguoc dna htuom sih ot tsif a desiar ylpmis rehsA
.eno ni sevlow owt
tdrahnieR	 .stnadnetta egairt eht fo seye eht ni semit ynam oot raf nees dah flesmih mailliW dnik eht
.enot ysae sih deileb seye esnet dna elims kaew s’ni-reppihw ehT
,lrans egavas a htiw gnitrotnoc ecaf sih
eH	 .sthgis s’elfir eht nwod derats eh
,sgnideecorp eht ot ycamitigel rehtruf dnel ot dna—
.bmot a morf htaerb a ekil
A	 ”.kcirt doog a evol od I
.taep neddos eht ot nworht saw mailliW dna
.swodahs eht ni dezilairetam ecaf s’tdrahnieR fo sruotnoc eht ,derats eh
eW“	 .ti lleuq ot gnihton did deviecer eh rewsna eht tub
.gniraelc eht otni ti dessot dna
taht ssefnoc tsum I hguoht
.dnuoh dezirp s’drol eht ,spaleaL ot dnet ot detnuomsid dah
,lessoR sa eman ym evag recuahC
”,ynnac s’eh
roirp seirutnec tohs neeb dah dnalgnE ni sevlow tsal eht taht nwonk dah mailliW ,yob a sa
.yks eht morf deniard thgil eht sa niarret reikcor otni dna sllih eltneg revo enil eht gniwollof ,roops eht ot gnipeek elbuort elttil dah sdnuoh
,tah demmirb-ediw a detser daeh sih pota dna
,denepo ecno ,srood emos dna
.srehto eht rof gnitiaw tuohtiw ssenkrad eht otni decnavda eH
.hself sih otni repeed reve knas llihc rettib ehT	 .seugnot neila ni gnas yeht sa gninetsil
A“	 ”.yllof rof kcal sti ron…“
…sretsnom eurt ylno eht era uoy taht sevlesruoy ecnivnoc ot deganam ev’uoY
.tnuom sih fo kcen eht dekorts
.evom ot nigeb dnah nwo sih tlef mailliW ,tnemom a retfA
dnes ll’ew yb ’nA      yennips ’na ael yreve hguorht toor ’nA      ,seinnih em hctef ll’ha ’na sdnuoh em hctef ll’ha oS      !’ninnuc si‘ tsniaga
.egailof eht morf deppets regnarts eht
sihT“	 .mih ecaf ot kcab denrut neht
,egdelwonk taht ni dnA
.hcnilf sa hcum os ton did erutaerc eht tub—
,spil sih ot regnif a tup nam ehT
yB	 .nmuloc detnuom a fo daeh eht ta ecalp fo tuo dekool evah ton dluow reilavac dlo eht ,mrofinu fo tfereb nevE
,denoitom regnarts
.retsaf taeb traeh sih ron ,redloc nur dluoc doolb sih thguoht ton dah eH
ehT	 .emit sih htrow saw retawkcab hsilgnE siht fi erus t’nsaw llits tsipaP eht ,llet dluoc mailliW sa raf sA
ehT	 .htaerb tsetfos eht tuo tel neht
…tsomla gnihtemos dnuof eh
.ssarg eht depmats resruoc sih sa dennirg reppepluC droL ,edis s’mailliW yB
.ti ees ot elba gnieb tuohtiw
,giwt gnihctarcs ro hguob gniltsur yrevE
,elponitnatsnoC ni egairt eht ni gniyd dna daed eht tsdima gniyl dellacer
ehT	 .ereh meht nward dah lavirra esohw srengierof fo riap eht nopu llef ezag s’mailliW
”?naem uoy od tahW“	 ”.ydaer
…tahW“	 .deilper tdrahnieR
modsiw a sessessop swodahs morf seelf ohw yob ehT“ .elkcuhc laitseb
,detpure gniyab dna gnikrab fo romalc
.esrevart ot sesroh rof hguone eltneg dna ediw ,ecaf ffilc eht gnidnecsed htap a ot noitnetta s’ytrap eht werd rehsA	 .yerflap sih detnuomer eh ,neetnac sih morf gnippis retfA
,esolc deretsulc seidob tlef
.llihc rettib a fo staerht derepsihw dniw tfos a ,hgih no morf gnidnecsed elihw
,doots tdrahnieR siht tA
,hsurbrednu eht ni dehsalf tessur fo kaerts
.moolg eht ni dedolpxe elfir a dna
thgil tsetniaf eht neve“
elihW	 .hcnerF tsomla saw taht
.erah dednuow a gnivresbo xof a ekil mih deiduts
.swodahs eht morf mih gnihctaw tnemelC rongisnoM thguac eh ,eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuO
.nam on saw ti taht ees dluoc mailliW ,neht yb dna—
,tor fo keer eht dna redwop kcalb fo egnis eht dellems dah eH	 .dehgis mailliW
.tsae eht ot sgarc neddos-niar eht revo
.ylthgils tah sih gnikcoc erofeb kaolc sih fo psalc eht gnitsujda
.ot dedeen t’ndah eH
…ssefnoc tsum I dnA“
,htuoy sih morf emyhr dlo na dnim ot thguorb atsiv ehT
.rahc gnikoms fo elip a otni gnizag
raen sward yef dna llef egasiv sA tsac ot mrof a tuohtiw
.hsurb eht otni repeed desserp yeht sa srepolretni eht dnuora gnisolc ,tsaef ot regae sdrib noirrac dnasuoht a fo snolat eht
,ssacrac eht fo noitcepsni sih detelpmoc enolerT rotcoD sA
,ylatI nrehtron fo seitic emitiram eht ta detnih tnecca esohw
,namhsleW deye-yleets ,nrets a
.deddon ylerem eh
dnas ekil esraoc eciov a ni demaercs dna demaercs dah nam ehT
.nwo s’mailliW sa enimrac sa doolb sih tub
.wonk ot saw ereht lla saw tI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.yas I sa od dna ,em raen peeK“
,erom sdnoces wef a rof hcterts ecnelis eht gnittel retfA
.kcab deppets mailliW ,don a htiW
eW“	 .tnemeerga ni derumrum nem eht fo lareveS
.redluohs sih no dnah a decalp dna revo deddolp noskcaJ moT ,egdel eht ediseb doots eh
t’ndluohS“	 .noitcideneb a rettum ot nageb tsipaP eht ,wodahs rieht nI
.taoc sih htaeneb neve delkcirp smra sih fo niks eht sa denekciuq traeh s’mailliW
”.sruoy tsniaga stiw ym tes ot ekil hcum yrev dluow I rof