si yrots s’yadoT dna
.niaga gnittuc tuohtiw epoc ot elba eb ll'eh
.ylevitatnet ksa I "?ronoC"
enim tsniaga elzzum sih sbur ronoC
.og ot evah t'ndid uoy hsiw I" .sffins eH ".oot
,mih gnidloh m'I elihw ,nehT
nihc ym seson ronoC  .ylteiuq yas I
redluohs rehto ym ot potpal krow ym gnidloh gab eht tfihs I
,tnemom taht ni yaw emas eht sleef eh enigami I
.ruf denniht yllanoisseforp ym revoc ot taocaep loow yvaeh ym no llup I ,rood eht tuo yaw ym nO
,ecir eht ot rageniv eht gnidda htiw trats em sah eH
»?sdem ruoy pu kcip ot em deeN
raey tsal saw eh naht won elbats erom s'eH .ylthgils sesae
.flesmih esoht sehsinif dna em seucser ronoC ,yletanutroF
,bojwolb a mih dereffo dna thginot ecalp s'xelA ta pu dewohs ronoC fI
tsehc ym ni erusserp ehT ".enola
.tset ym gnikat saw I elihw seirecorg eht tog dna tekram hsif eht ot tnew eh ,puY"
.sgaw liat siH .ksa I
.si eh llams woh evol I
enO raeY - tcejorP noitamalceR ehT ni sraeppa
.srae sih neewteb elzzum ym tser ot nwod dneb neht dna ssik eht nruter I
taht gnihgual em tsniaga snael eh sa neht s'tI
.ssik a otni mih llup I dna
,noitats niart dedworc eht ot teg I nehW
ecalp s'xelA ta thgin eht dneps dna pu siht lla kcap nac I ,tuo og ot tnaw uoy fI"
.hcum elttil a eb nac yteixna sih semitemos tub htaed ot mih evol I
.yab eht ssorca llor spac etihw ,wodniw eht edistuO
.nooS« .deksa eh tahw rewsna tsuj I
,tnecca reporp eht evah ot deliaf rotca na emit hcae
.meht dias eh teY
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
»): ?thginot gniod ew era tahW
.gninrom siht saw eh naht yffulf ssel yltnacifingis s'eh ezilaer I
.thginot eivom a dna rennid tsuj naht erom tnaw ot gniog s'eh wonk I
.stnemngissa krowemoh sseldne htiw emoc hcihw fo htob
tsuj seirotS RE laeR fo nosaes wen eht ,sediseB"
.gnitaeb emit drah a evah dluow etoyoc a taht nirg a em sevig ronoC
VT eht hctaw ot denrut htob era sdaeh ruO
",ylimaf ym esol ot tnaw t'nod I dna
.sllor ihsus ekam ot woh nrael I ,thginoT
,raey tsal eht ni ssergorp fo tol a edam ev'eW
".yawa thgir kcab llac dna moor eht evael ll'I
.gniod neeb s'eh tahw ezilaer I nehw s'taht dna
,snoitpo ruo stimil ygrella xetal siH
"!mraw yatS .syadiloh yppaH"
"?ruf ruoy ot deneppah tahW"
pis a naht erom gnihtynA
.ecir gnikooc fo llems eht dna
.noonretfa siht taht ekil gnihtemos dias evah yam xof der niatrec A"
",uoy ssim ot gniog m'I"
.ecalp ni nalp a sah ydaerla eh esuaceb sesimorp yna rof hsup ro sdnamed yna ekam t'nod I
.bojwolb reporp a evig ot woh mih gnihcaet
",tnemtrapa eht gninaelc rof uoy knahT"
.enim tsniaga drah si noitcere siH
.tuo denniht ruf sih dah eh yhw dnatsrednu I
nac eh syaw ynam sa ni
.semitemos tluciffid si pihsnoitaler ruO
ti dna semit nezod a eivom siht nees htob ev'eW
,snoisses ypareht ylkeew elpitlum dna loohcs sah ronoC
.ti ot delpats repap eht kcehc dna
.tol a nialpxe dluow taht
,ssik eW ".eromyna toN"
hcuoc eht fo edis eht tsniaga dekcut kcapkcab s'ronoC ees I nehT
siht ekil mih gnildduC
.daetsni sehtolc s'rehto hcae gnivomer trats ew
,xof fo ksum tniaf eht yb dewollof
.traeh ym no ylivaeh shgiew
.revo flah saw eivom eht erofeb knurd tuokcalb su evah dluow
.ffur kcen ym ni elzzum sih seirub eH ".noonretfa
kcab sih nwod edils swap yM
.dlo eht fo pot no sracs wen leef d'I
,sexaler em fo trap rehtonA
.tnemetatsrednu na si llew ti eldnah t'ndid ronoC taht yas oT
.htron pu gniiks gniog si ylimaf yM .haN"  ".thgilnus gnidnilb eht ni ekab dna esuoh ’stnerap ym ot em htiw gnola emoc uoy t'nod yhW"
,gnikooc s'eh ,detcepsus I sA
.feiler a si hcihw ,cinam eb ot mlac oot yletinifed s'eH  .mih erussaer I
noacyL edoyaK yb
.rrup a htiw ksa I
esolc si ydob siH
.thginot gnihtyna od ot ygrene eht evah t'nod I dna yadnuS enalp a no gnivael m'I
,niap fo enotrednu na htiw meht syas eh won nevE
.yteixna dellortnocnu fo skeew lareves htiw dedne sreziliuqnart htiw tnemirepxe tsal s'ronoC
.yldednah-ffo yas I
”thgiN etaD“   :yojne esaelP  .oc.edoyak etisbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,tenalPruF yb
",tuo gniog fo daetsni ni gnitae er'ew esoppus I"
,ronoC ot tnatropmi si xeS
,uoy dlot enoyna saH"
tsuj m'I ,krow htiw gnilaed retfa tuB
.ylper ym tuoba kniht ot niart eht no detaes ylbatrofmoc m'I litnu tiaw I »*enihw
.tcepxe dluow esle enoyna naht erom
.taht ssecorp ot tnemom a em sekat tI ".ees ll'uoY"
,hguone t'nsaw taht fI
,keew siht etad a dah t'nevah llits ew
.keew yreve ygrene eht dnif ot em rof drah neeb s'ti yletaL
,tnemtrapa llams ruo ot rood eht tA
evots eht no ecir fo top a s'ereht ,nehctik eht nI
»?ihsuS«  .semoc reven ti ylno
niks ruo tsniaga rehtegot gnidils ruf ruo leef oT
.enim ton yletinifed si wohs etirovaf s'ronoC
,taerg sleef ti dna ,doog s'eH
sgaw liat siH ".wonk I"
.eniw fo pis a koot ew
.enim tsniaga pu desserp htaehs sih leef nac I tub
.nrut ym yllacinhcet saw tI .ksa I
,evol hcum sa mih evig ot tnaw I dna
,era owt rehto eht dna
.niaga meht yrt ot tnatiseh neeb dah eH
,thgin etad a s'ti hguoht nevE
ydaer era sdem s'ronoC em gnillet ycamrahp eht morf si egassem enO
",emit a ta gniht enO" ".secivreS
",xelA dna sdem ym evah ll'I .ebyaM"
.llew noitarapes eldnah t'nseod llits ronoC
.dnatsrednu I yaw a ni ti nialpxe ot elba neeb reven s'eh tub
.ssik feirb a em evig ot seot sih fo spit eht no sdnats eh dna
.gnihctac morf ti peek ot stuc neewteb efink eht epiw ot woh em swohs eH
.erutcip eht otni xes gnignirb tuohtiw nruter ni emas eht od ot em gniwolla dna
.trap ew erofeb nac I sa ecnarussaer dna ,xes
.sthgin etad no tuo og yllausu eW .ddo si hcihw
taht od nac I yaw ylno ehT
,retteb wonk t'ndid I fI
.niart eht nO
,dnatsrednu reven dluow stnerap yM"
esolc steg eh sa tnap mih gnihctaW
,eson ym stluassa renaelc nomel fo llems eht ,ti nepo I nehW
,elbaton t'nsi tnecs s'ronoC
.enim tsniaga mraw dna
.tuo nrow dna derit oot
uoY« .gnitsuahxe eb ot gniog si yadrutaS
.em rof hguone doog s'tahT
.enola eb em tel t'now eH
,oga raey a tsomla ,os su rof drow hguone gnorts a t'nsaw rentraP
.ttub sih ezeeuqs nac I os srexob sih rednu nwod edils swap ym nehT
,yrt I drah woh rettam oN
.reh ta yllufyalp taws I  .sesaet ehs
»?thginot eivom a dna rennid tsuj htiw yako
.mih htiw emagdraob a gniyalp yppah sa tsuj eb dluow I tub
.egrahcer ot ffo thginot gnikat yb si
.won em gnillik s'tahw s'taht dnA
truh erom neeb dah ronoC dna
.eciov napdaed a ni ylper I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dekrep llits srae
.oot eM"  .ylteiuq yas I
.soediv desahcrup ruo ot setagivan dna etomer eht pu skcip ronoC
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.yhw wonk ot ekil d'I tub
niponolK rof noitpircserp wen a s'tI
.reerac gnitirw sih tuo gnitrats tsuj si ohw flow detniap suoiragerg a
-srentrap citsemod--deirram htob er'ew ,repap nO
"?gnisoohc er'uoy esoppus I"
.gniyfsitas ylpeed si
".denniht ti teg ot tuo em koot xelA"
,rehtruf yna hsup t'nseod eh tub
.tuo em swollof ,eciffo ym edistuo sebuc eht ni maet tnempoleved eht morf drapoel wons wollef a ,haraS
stniop gnorts ym fo eno t'nsi gnikooC
.rebmucuc a gnitcessid ylluferac no desucof si ronoC
,ni gnitae era ew esruoc fo ,noitseuq yllis a s'tI
.ebircsed t'nac I yoj a si
.xelA dneirf sih ylbaborp si xof eht os ,setammoor evah t'nod eW
.tey ereht etiuq ton m'I tub ydaer s'eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.em txet nac xelA ro uoy
.rennid htiw mih pleh ot em setivni eh nehT .sgaw liat siH ".gnizigolopa
,mih rof drah a eb ot gniog si keew eritne na tub
.doog ytterP" .ksa I
sllor ihsus ekam ot tam gnillor eht gnisu snrut ekat eW ".togrof I"
.segassem eerht era erehT
.trapa emoc yeht ,enim ot teg ew nehw
.pu em sekohc etammaet sih em gnillac miH
si tnemtrapa eht si eciton I gniht txen ehT
.kcab ym no nwod yal I elihw em fo pot no syal eh ,daetsnI
elzzum sih ni eceip a evohs I sa selggig ronoC
"?yako eb uoy lliW"
# # # .no gniog s'tahw rednow dna
.gnol os rof ni devil dah eh riapsed eht otni nwod kcab mih llup dna
.eciffo ym fo tuo teg neve nac I erofeb sgnid enohp yM
,dehsinif si ihsus eht ecnO ".spahreP"
.flow ralopib etirovaf ym morf ,esruoc fo
nehW« .ti tuoba romuh fo esnes a sah eh tsael tA
.ti debircserp dah ehs desirprus m'I hguohT
,tnemugra elbativeni eht rof tiaw I nehT .ksa I
.enoyna tsuj htiw xes evah dluow eh naem t'ndid
.tuo eugnot sih skcits eH ".gnineve
,em ta kool ot snrut eH
mih dnuora mra ym parw I
nissassa tnatculer a tuoba ”ekaL nedraG kraD“ yrots siH
.edisni eht no devargne si eman s'ronoC
.ksa I "?yhw snevaeH"
.stnerap retsof ym htiw yats nac ew dna em htiw pu emoC .etammaet ym er'uoY"
sehtaerb eh dna kcab s'ronoC bur swap yM
.syawedis srae sih
,yteirbos fo stifeneb eht gnirevocsid
.revo klaw dna ,sih ot txen roolf eht no gab ym tes
em sevol eh wohs ot troffe fo tol a gnikam s'eh
,tnetnoc tsomla ,ylisae
,hcum oot struh ti fI"
meht llet I hcum woh rettam on sdrapoel wons elbigile htiw pu em kooh ot gniyrt peek dna
.evom tsrif eht ekam ot em gnitivni
.noitnetta hcum gniyap si su fo rehtien tub
.dneirf tseb detseretninu dna thgiarts yrev sih--xelA kcuf ot noissimrep ronoC gnivig fo ekatsim eht edam ecno I
.em dna ,ylimaf s'xelA
ronoC tuoba wonk t'nod yehT
.em llik dluow xelA
.pu peek t'nac I taht netfo os ti stnaw eh dna em rof tnereffid tsuj s'tI .od I
,yadirF ydaerla s'tI
eceip tsal eht neeb dah sdrow esoht fi sa
".flow trams a er'uoy
.mih naht reggib si krow ym ta etoyoc yreve
.guh eltneg a ni mih parw I
.raey tsal eht ni noitacidem htiw luferac neeb dna rebos deyats s'eh
,eno koot eh fI .redluohs sih bur I ".gninrom
.eye eht ni em kool ot pu stis eH ".og
"?siht nalp uoy pleh xelA"
.sih ta mih htiw gniyats eb ll'I neht dna stnerap retsof ym ta em htiw gniyats s'eH" .seilper eh
.gninrom siht em rof ni ti dexaf ehs ,yadretsey tsirtaihcysp ym deliame I"
.siht deganam eh woh wonk t'nod I
.sraet ot em sgnirb tsomla
suoiruf neeb dah xelA
.sredluohs ym ffo keew eht fo sserts eht sekat
,su neewteb thgiew hcum os yrrac sdrow eerht esohT
.gnikrow morf gniod s'eh tahw pots t'nseod taht tub si laog sih tahw erus ytterp m'I
.eno retrohs hcum ym gnola gnidils eugnot gnol sih
.elbat eeffoc eht no sbmurc ro roolf doowdrah eht no sehtolc on era erehT .naelc
.liat sih fo edis rehtie no tser ot
.yrdnual ylkeew dna sehsid naht erom seod eh tsisni t'nod I os ,krowloohcs sih htiw pu gnipeek elbuort hguone sah eH
"?siht teg uoy did nehW"
,noacyL edoyaK yb ”thgiN etaD“
.dnabsuh rehto hcae llac ot ydaer era su fo rehtien tub-
retnuoc eht no ycamrahp erots yrecorg eht morf gab dedracsid a eciton I nehT
.cinam gniog trats ot mih rof emit dab yllaer a si sihT
gab nrot eht barg ot revo pets I
.keew lla gnitiaw retfa mih ot riaf t'nsi tsuj yad rehtona ffo mih gnihsuP
pu sbmuht a mih dnes I
taorht sih psarg ot tuo gnihcaer saw tsap eht fi sa
.htaerb peed a ekat I
,gniknird fo daetsni ,emit sihT
.kcohs a lla s'tI
.seceip laudividni otni sllor eht ecils I
.egaugnal ngierof a kaeps ot sliaf yletulosba rotca xnyl suomaf eht retfa
.enohp ym kcehc dna
.eson sih kcil I nehT
,raey siht ebyam ,dna
.rehtegot emit lufgninaem yna dneps yldrah dluow ew esiwrehto esuaceb sthgin etad pu tes eW
.etaidemmi si ylper sih ,yletanutrofnU
.mih gnidloh evol I dna
.mih guh ot dnuora hcaer I nehw eltrats t'nseod eh os ,elit eht no teef ym ffucs I
.ylrae emoh eb d'I mih desimorp I dna
.epoN« .setunim neetfif tsal eht rof enohp sih ta gnirats neeb ylbaborp s'eH
moor gnivil eht ot draob gnittuc eht yrrac ew ,enod er'ew nehW
.yadot enod s'eh gnihtyreve tuoba yrrow ot nigeb dna
.retnuoc eht no repap rehctub nworb no hsif war fo dnik emos dna
,srepsihw dna sredluohs ym dnuora swap sih sparw eh nehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.meht yas ot elba neeb syawla t'nsah eH
gnikoj saw eh ,yletanutroF
.cidemarap a saw I nehw morf seiromem dab pu gnirb samard lacideM
.sneppah tahw rettam on ,rehtegot dneps ew gnineve eno eht eb ot desoppus era syadseuT
.niaga ,ronoC s'ti wonk I esuaceb hgis I
.samtsirhC rof seilimaf evitcepser ruo tisiv ot detarapes ew ,taht retfa thgir ,yletanutrofnU
.ysub yltnatsnoc em sah kroW
.lortnoc rednu sgniws doom sih peek ot enituor ydaets a sdeen ronoC
.elbat eeffoc eht no ti tes dna
,swalf sih lla roF
,txet revo tnemugra na evah dna noissucsid elohw taht trats naht rehtaR
.wap ym htiw ylgnivol elzzum sih ekorts I ".uoy evol yehT
.thgir tsuj sdrac eht lla gniyalp ,flow elttil revelc a er'uoY"
.rae sih ni repsihw dna
;flow a rof rednels dna trohs s'eH
.gnineve eht rof segelivirp VT ruoy tsol dna etal emoh erew uoY"
ta m'I erehw em teem ot gnitpmetta s'eh gniwonK
.eb lliw eh gnipoh ,ksa I
,gnineppah si tahw rettam oN
",etirovaf yM" ".tuo emac
.gnitad detrats ew ecnis em gnihcaet yltneitap neeb sah ronoC tub
.swap thgir ruo no sgnir ruo raew llits eW
elims a htiw seye ym llor I
.ti fo tnuoma llams a ton dna
dna sdem ym tog ew nehT
suovren*« »?emoh eb uoy lliw
.sthgin etad no pu semoc syawla gnihtemos
.detapicitna evah dluoc reve I naht
tsom naht retteb si seirotS RE laeR
,srexob ruo ot ylkciuq nwod htob er'eW
saw sihT     .ydaer m'I
.seilper eh ",thgiR"
.cilbup ni yteixna sih gnildnah ta ecitcarp ronoC sevig dna tnemtrapa eht fo tuo su steg ti tub
,em ta kool ot kcab daeh sih stlit ronoC
,stnerap retsof sih era tfel sah eh ylimaf ylno ehT
,noacyL edoyaK yb ”thgiN etaD“
ygrene ym fo tol a esu t'nseod tI .ffo mih wap I dna ,eldduc ew sthgin tsom ,esimorpmoc a sA
.poord srae sih nehT .ylduorp syas eh
wap thgir ym no gnir latem ehT
.nruter ni emas eht yas I sa rethgit elttil a mih dloh dna
.tuo eugnot reh skcits haraS ".htron
.dluow I ,em htiw emoh mih ekat dluoc I yaw emos saw ereht fI
,xes ekil t'nod I yas ot ton s'tahT
.hctaw ot em rof tluciffid llits era sedosipe eht fo emos tub
.rehtegot tnemtrapa eht denaelc
.em ot erom hcum os snaem meht gnivig syojne eh hcum woh gniees tub
.ylteiuq syas eh ",yakO"
.seod ti tub hgual em ekam t'ndluohs tahT ".bojwolb
,eert taoc eht no tekcaj retniw yvaeh ym pu gnah I "!nehctiK"
xes detnaw eh esuaceb tsuJ
.stnerap ym ot og I nehw em htiw--gnir eht neve ro--mih ekat ot elba eb t'now I
.senirambus dna seips gnivlovni eivom noitca redlo na skcip dna
.elzzup depahs-drapoel wons a fo
daeherof eht no mih ssik I ".uoy evol I"
.derewohs evah tsum eh os
,ronoC evol I hcum woh rettam oN
.tekcaj retniw a evah neve t'nod uoy dna htron sruoh owt si siweL"
".em rehtob t'nseod tI .xof citcra na htiw krow I .ronoC"
"?eivom eht gnihctaw uoY"
.hsipeehs snrut elims siH ".rehtegot
.nruter ni bojwolb a em evig mih tel ll'I ,elihw a ni ecnO
.tol gnikrap eht ot sdaeh haraS elihw noitats niart eht sdrawot klaw dna
"?taht rof ezigolopa ot deen I od semit ynam woH"
,hguone ton s'taht fI
.rehtruf gniog no ffo sdloh ronoC tub
".llems xof eht tuoba yrroS"
.nirg a htiw redluohs ym tsniaga daeh sih sbur eH ".evitom
,mra tfel sih gnola tlef I fI
erehw emag gniknird a deyalp ew
.secivreS tnedutS ni ti ekat ot dah llitS"
.niaga sgaw liat siH ".tekcaj
.ihsus rehto hcae gnideef snrut ekat ew
.evitom roiretlu na dah uoy tcepsus d'I
"?og lanif ruoy did woH"
.edis rehto eht no elbat dne eht no dekcats yltaen skoobtxet sih dna
.enim nodnaba ot em ksa t'ndluoc eH
.gnizigolopa pots reven ll'uoY"
tub ysae era dellor eh seno ehT
"?navonoD ,yadot dloc tib A"
.ytnelp si seviw-xe owt gnivah
,samtsirhC gnirud yllaicepse
,draob gnittuc eht gninaelc retfa neht dna
",emit artxe yna deen t'ndiD
".ti etaicerppa yllaer I" .yas I
.ot sdeen eh fi tuo hcaer ot mih tsurt si od nac I llA
.ydaer yllanif erew ew litnu setammaet eb ot degdelp ew
.niaga gnitarapes era ew woN
,baher ni shtnom eerht tneps ronoC erofeB .dlo steg reven