,nomed deeps a ekil airetefac eht fo tuo gniylF
,dias gnihtyna tahw eulc on dah eh hguoht
,ffo flesmih gnivaw erofeb dnoces a rof delbmuts siuoL
ees tsum uoy taht meop a evah I
”.eeffoc ruoy fo llems eht ekil I“ .ni denael dna
.dekcilc reven ti yhw derednow syawla eH
,ylsuoicarg eton eht koot nairB
;ti rof pu tlef reven eh ,lleW
,sucof emos niager ot gniyrT
.yllaidroc ekops yeht sa rehtona eno htiw elbatrofmoc gnitteg
”.ynnuf yrev lla era uoy ,ahaH
,terces a ti ekam t’ndid nairB
.pup ynihw elttil a ekil kool d’eh taht dias eh fi tub
,gniht elgnis a tuo tel dluoc eh erofeb tsuj eh dna delwarc ecap siH
.egap thgir eht dnuof eh litnu dnuorg eht ot gnitaolf emac sfael esooL
,moor eht depolevne ssenllits eiree nA
.taes sih fo tuo pu depmuj oot eh sa mih rof ti deifiralc tar eht
,maerdyad eht morf delzzarf elttil a llitS
,rewsna na teg ot gnipoh ,netram eht deksa siuoL ”?yako eh sI“
,dne dluoc sgniht denigami eh taht syaw fo sdnasuoht dna sderdnuh eht lla fo tuo taht ,mih no denwad tI
,esolc os saw eh elihw yawa pils ot ecnahc siht gnitnaw ton ,etarepseD
.noitnetta s’siuoL tog ti esuaceb
pil sih no wang saw od dluoc nairB llA
.yob rehto eht morf yawa denrut ylwols nairB ,sgel sih neewteb dekcut liaT ?ti saw
ti draeh ohw enoyna edam yllaretil dah ti taht
.morf ettal sih teg dluow hateehc eht taht eno eht dnuof eh litnu nwot eritne eht ni pohs eeffoc yreve ta tis dluow eh
,nwos dnah dekool einaeb dna fracs neerg gnihctam siH .ni deklaw siuoL
,eno taht htiw yawa deirrac elttil a teg noitanigami sih tel evah thgim eh ,yakO
?syawyna taht saw nalp esohW
.raepsekahS neve dna ,tsorF
.kaeps ot flow hsipeehs won eht rof detiaw eh elihw wap eno ni sreksihw desiar sih delriwt siuoL
,deunitnoc nairB sa nwod tnew swap sih ,yllaudarG
.hsoG hO ”.em ta kool uoY“
,yllamron ekam dluow eh senil tcaxe prahs eht fo daetsnI
,hcnerF ni neeb evah llew dah thgim draob eht no gnihtyrevE
!mih rof tuo ti evah did yllaer ehS
.yad yreve htiw tas d’eh taht netram dna tar emas eht htiw kcab eht ni gnittis siuoL ees dluoc eH
.mih htiw yawa nur noitanigami sih gnittel erom oN
.dnuora kcab thgir nups dna redluohs sih debbarg wap a
,mih tpecca ro tcejer ot rewop eht htiw eno eht eb dluow nairB
,mih thgif t’ndid eH
.niaga mih ta kcab ecnalg ot ylno
,pu siht ssem ot secnahc erom on dna ecneidua eht ta pu ecnalg tsal enO
.mih rof tsuj ereht gnitiaw erew spuc owt dna
,skeew wef a naht ssel nI
.dab os t’nsaw tahT
?sdnuos taht bmud woh eeS
”.tnuocca knab ym detfardrevo yllatnedicca ev’thgim I
.gnicar saw traeh sih naht retsaf gaw liat s’nairB edam lla
.emankcin elttil etuc a eb dluow taht ebyaM
,hguoht ti fo ytilaer eht t’nsaw yllaer tahT
.tnemssarrabme hsiyob dna elims neewteb derevaw noisserpxe s’siuoL
,gnah tib tsal taht gnitteL
,hateehc citnarf eht nwod mlac ot gniyrt tsuj won tub ,desufnoC .emac enoN
,naem I .uoy gniwollof ton ,oN“
.emit tsrif eht rof fi sa tsomla mih ot gninetsil ,dekrep srae sih dna dekcoc worbeye s’siuoL
,yeknod a saw taht retfA
,lla ta seitivitca ralucirrucartxe on
gniyas saw flow eht lleh eht tahw dnatsrednu ot ni gninael deirt elbat eht ta syob ehT
.syob rehto ni detseretni saw wonk neve t’ndid eh taht yob a rof siht lla dna ,sdnoces ni dnim sih dnuora spal gninnur saw hateehc tahT
,tsehc sih morf detpure hgual dekohc A
.ti rof pu leef t’ndid yllaer eh dna txen saw EP
,ta kool ot yllis saw nirg enipul gnol s’flow eht esuaceb saw ti ebyaM
.emit eritne eht nepo ediw waj tas siuoL
.krow ot gniog saw sihT
.mrof rednels s’hateehc eliga eht ot demrof taht sfeirb eulb thgirb
.tfos rehtaef eb ot dekool eh ,esool dna gnol os ruf dna dnuor tib a saw taht eromohpos a
stcejorp gnitirw suoirav no skrow
:seinohc sih ot nwod saw siuoL
,rehtaew retniw looc siht nI
?lairetam dneirfyob dnuos taht seoD
.gnihtemos yas ot mih rof gnitiaw yltneitap dna ecnaraeppa neddus s’flow eht ta desufnoc
.siuoL ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut tub
,dna ,mih gniyduts
.yaw eht fo tser eht krow ot teef sih teg ot evif rehtona gnikat won saw dna
.thgif a ni neeb reve ev’I kniht t’nod I ,heh
.won reviaw t’ndluoc eh tub
.eil a eb yllautca t’ndluow ti
,demrasid tub ,deretsulF
,yletilop elzzum sih deppid dna enil eht sdrawot walc a detniop hateehc eht
.dekcus ylsuoires meop taht tub
,elbissop sa ylteiuq dna yletilop sa flesmih desucxe eH
.deklaw eh sa stneduts rehto eht gnigdod ,sehcneb eht dnuora ssorca yaw sih edam eh
.egareva ylriaf eb ot demees eh ,mih ekil tsuj dna
.semitemos ffo tfird I .yrros ,haey ,hO“
.wenk eh tahw tsniaga melborp eht ni ta saw eh erehw tuo krow ot gniyrt
,htiw pu emoc ot deirt eh nalp tahw rettam oN
”.ecin kool uoy kniht I ,tsuj—I
.gag deniartser rehtona saw tuo emac taht lla dna gnihtemos yas ot deirt hateehc eht ,niagA
,krow t’nseod rohpatem eht ebyaM
,dekrep srae dna pu nihc sih htiw smoor rekcol eht otni gnippetS
.drawrof puc toh eht gnihcni dna elbat eht ssorca gnihcaer ,detrats eh ”,yllautca ,hO“
.htapohcysp etelpmoc a ekil gnikool ton ta deliaf eh erom eht gnitaropave ylkciuq saw dah eh taht tbuod eht fo tifeneb revetahW
.sag fo tuo rac a ekil gnirettups ,deliart eh
.enilef eht eltrats ot hguone
.yaw sih nirg a dessap dna nitsuD ta ecnalg eno thguac eH
.nrut ot nageb daeh sih ni sleehw ehT
,teef sih ot pu tohs eH
.nairB tnorfnoc ot gniyrt ,detrats siuoL
.taes nepo eht ni tas dna revo dellorts eh
,flow gnimaeb llits eht dna puc eht pota fael klim demaets eht neewteb gnitrad seyE
.reffo eht ta deddon siuoL erofeb dnoces a rof rehto hcae dleh snoisserpxe bmud riehT
.noitseggus diputs a tahW
.noitcif yrruf citore trohs dna ,allevon a
.efac eht ni elzzum yreve debbarg ti taht ylduol os riahc sih kcab dehcoocs eh
.mih ni detseretni t’nsaw eh thguoht eh ,tsael tA
.yaw ”?ti tuoba od annog ahctahw“ a ni sredluohs sih deggurhs nairB
.taht ot timda t’ndluow eh tub
.gnitivni os demees tsuj ti
.ti ot dehcatta erew sgnirts fi sa gnisiar doow fo eceip ffits a ekil dekool ti ,yltsoM
.erif no luos s’flow eht til eh woh ton wenk eh fi sa koobeton sih ni yawa gnilbbircs tsuj ,saw eh erehT
mih llik ot gniog saw hguoht siuoL htiw ssalc rehtonA .EP gnikaerf s’ti
.noitanigami evitcarevo sih tsuj saw gnihtyreve taht dab tlef eh ,tsrif tA
.rehtegot sevlesmeht eceip ot nageb sgniht
?gnihtemos yas ot dah syawla taht eno eht eh saw yhW
.nwo sih neewteb sregnif nworb yddum sih ecalretni ot flow eht gniwolla
,erutan ydeeps sih ekilnu ,yllufknahT
.uoy gniklats t’nsaw I
.gnitpecca sa etiuq ton saw haraS
,etoyoC triD yb ”gnimaerdyaD“
.knarp on s’erehT .oN ?tahW“
,eralg rehtona mih evag ehS
,elbat eht evael ot ecnahc a teg neve t’ndid netram ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .sevitcepsporP
.gnitirw saw eh tahw ees ot redluohs s’siuoL revo keep a kaens dna yrt dluow nairB ,netfO
,ni detseretni ro detseretni etiuq reven
,dnuora stug sih gnitsiwt stonk eht htiW
.no tup eh trihs-t yerg eht rednu deraeppasid elzzum sih sa emit sih gnikat saw siuoL
,wam sih fo epag thgils eht morf
meht knaht dluow eh
.skeehc sih fo etihw eht hguorht tuc tnit der a dna detfil sreksihw s’enilef ehT
,tsacdop ybgur rieht no ot netsil osla nac uoy ohw
.ti tuoba yas ot gnitseretni gnihtemos evah dluoc eh taht os tsuj ti fo yna dnatsrednu dluoc eh taht drah os dehsiw nairB
.ksed sih delttar ti taht drah os dekrej nairB
.nworf a tub gnihton htiw tfel saw eh litnu tib yb tib dellevarnu elims sih
”.uoy deciton evah I“
.syart citsalp dna stneduts htiw dellif ydaerla erew selbat eht fo tsoM
.ylkciuq oot ti fo tnorf ni thgir gnidnats ot elbat eht morf ecnatsid elbissopmi na gnieb morf tnew eh ,tnatsni na
.noitommoc eht nrecsid ot gniyrt dnuora gnikcilf daeh s’siuoL fo pot no sehsid dnuor owt eht ees dluoc nairB ,mih fo tnorf nI
,noitcudortni yls sih
,dexelprep yllauqe tas sdneirf siH
hguor eb thgim tI
,kcen sih dnuora ti dessot dna fracs sih fo dloh debbarg eH ”.ffo ssip ,esaelP
.erehwyna gniog ton saw elims s’nairB
,sesnes dinac sih rof evitisnes elttil a saw eeffoC
.kcab eht sdrawot eurt tpek eh
,erew snoitnetni sih tahw wenk ydoboN
.revo semit noillim a sey eb dluow rewsna sih wenk ydaerla eh dna
,pool kcabdeef emos ni thguaC
.ecaf sih sdrawot thgiarts gnihsalps emoc ettal toh eht saw gniees nairB gniht tsal eht dna
.hsart eht otni drah gnilruh erofeb teksabetsaw tseraen eht ot ti ekam ylno ot deganam tar eht ,dneirf sih sa tsaf sa ylraen toN
,erofeb ekil tsuJ
,APG 8.2 a htiw ,)tib elttil yrev
.citamard elttil a ,niaga ,lleW
,mih morf yawa sdray wef a ylno saw ti hguoht nevE
.tsrif noitseuq sih htiw ffo mih tuc siuoL
.tcefrep eb ot gniog saw ti wenk eh
,dehtuom dna haraS ta tniuqs a kcab tohs eh
,elzzum dna srae s’enipul eht revo dehsulf tnemssarrabme toh deR
,yawa ti lliw ot deirt eh drah woh rettam oN
.gnihtemos tuoba desufnoc er’uoy nehw ,won thgir ekil ,ecnad elttil taht od srae ruoy yaw eht ekil I“
.mih rof sgnileef sih ssefnoc ot eno eht eb dluoc siuoL dna ecno siht tsuj ssap eerf a teg eh t’ndluoC
saw sihT    .nrut ot nageb
.tnemeerga ni gniddon dna pu ti gninepo erofeb daeh sih gniwob
.spil nwo sih morf yawa sehcni tsuj saw ti litnu resolc werd tuons llams s’siuoL ,ni gninaeL
.eurt nmad os tlef esle gnihtyreve tub
,ffo reh deggurhs eh nehW
,strohs myg sih tuo gnillup dna raewrednu nwo sih ot nwod gnippirtS
.taorht sih dnuora delruc ti sa tsuj ydob eritne sih gnitsiwt
,srevir dna spordniar
.yas ot sdrow rof gnilbmuf tfel eno eht won saw eh ,dehsabA
,rekcol sih fo edisni eht no sucof ot deirt nitsuD taht emit yrevE
.yadot tuoba tnereffid saw gnihtemos gnisnes
”.uoy rof siht tog I“
,evael dna gab sih barg ot thguoht eh nehw tsuj dna gninrom lla ereht gnittis neeb d’eH
dog os saw meop sih taht ezilaer eh did neht ylnO
,deksa dna tuo flesmih denethgiarts ,detartsurf dna deyonna elttil a ,siuoL
,gnihtyna yas dluoc eh erofeb tub ,edutitta ni nrut prahs s’hateehc eht deciton nairB
si yrots s’yadoT dna
a( ytfeh tib elttil a
,regguR .P .B yb uoy rof daer
,trats dluow ssalc erofeB
”.em esucxe“ ,gnilbmum
.swap devooh sih dniheb ecaf sih edih ot gniyrt elihw moor rekcol eht fo tuo ffo demrots
:egap eht ffo eurt sdrow eht daer dna
,dlrow laer eht ot kcab flesmih gnikahS
.stnemgarf laiborcim otni derettahs traeh no depmots s’nairB .ezorf emiT
.dnuora nrut t’ndid eh yllufknaht tub
,reguR .P .B yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
,he ,ym neeb tsuj evah tsum tI“
.flesmih dnim ot flow eht ecrof dna noitcerid reh tnes noitnetta teg ot esion gnikam dna gnihguoc
dna hcnerF ni erew smeop eht fo tsoM
”,derebmemer uoy ,haey ,htaM“
.eton elgnis a nekat t’ndah eh dna revo tsomla saw ssalC .did ydaerla
,ni gninetsil neeb dah airetefac eritne eht fi sA .lli yllacisyhp
,gniyas erofeb flow eht ezorf eh
,tnemtimmoc sih hguorht wollof ot egaruoc hguone pu krow ot gniyrt edistuo dnats ot setunim net nairB koot tI
,koobeton sih ni sdrow nwod gnittoj neewteB
,eromyna hateehc eht rof ton hguoht ,elims sih ,nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon nairB
,tsehc nwo sih tsniaga ylthgit depparw koobetoN
,hguoht ti tuoba gniknihT
nairB	 .elzzum sih ot wap sih gnidloh dna
”.tsrif ettal ym gnitteg tsuj ma I .eruS“
,gnignahc dna gniklaw deirt eh sA
taes ytpme nA .elbat eht ta gnittis flow kcalb dna nworb eht deciton eh taht ereht saw tI
.ti yas ot woh wonk t’ndid nairB esuaceb wonk t’ndid eh ,llew ,yllautcA
,sseuS hguorht gniruop tneps erew skeew rof thgin yrevE .nrut ot nageb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,diputs t’nsaw ti ,thgirlA
.dnim s’nairB fo tuo syob rehto eht lla gnisahc saw hateehc eht esuaceb saw ti ebyam ,lleW
.deraeppa yeht hcihw ni redro yna gniwonk tuohtiw esnes elttil edam sworra dna ,sehsals ,slobmys ,srebmun ehT
.seye sih desolc dna
.sroinuj htob er’eW .nairB m’I ,iH
.gnimaerdyad erom oN
,mih no tup ylgnittiwnu flow eht lleps eht morf eerf flesmih kaerb ot elba yllanif
.yllacizziuq ni denael dna
.yawa ti epiw ’ndluoc eh tub
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih wolloF
.mih dnuora stneduts rehto eht otni gnikconk tsomla ,ecnalab sih esol dluow nairB
”.htam erahs eW .siuoL“
?flesmih smeti wef a evomer tsael ta eh dluohs
.dneirf doog a eb ot tuo ekam ot gniog saw dna ,taerg saw siuoL
,dlrow elohw eht ni hateehc suoegrog tsom eht rof gninip saw traeh siH
.yad lla gnihtyna etirw ot tey d’eh ezilaer ot ylno seton sih ot noitnetta sih denrut eh
.mraw mih peek yllautca dluoc taht gnihtemos naht stnerapdnarg sih morf tfig a ekil erom
,yob xof ssorc siht saw erehT
.elzzum nedlog trohs nwo sih ssorca ylsuoigatnoc peerc ot nageb ylwols elims a tub
.riaf yllaer t’nsaw taht ,eniF .os kniht t’ndiD
.foog a ekil gnitca mih hctac ot hateehc eht gnitnaw ton
,swap sih gnibbuR
,saw taht lleh eht tahw rednop neve dluoc eh erofeB
.tnemetats sih kcab deklaw hateehc eht
s’siuoL	 .elcarim a rof yarp dna
.erats gnilbuort s’hateehc eht morf mih fo tuo thgir deppas neeb dah ygrene dna msimitpo eht fo llA
.laticer sih pu dehsinif flow eht litnu sevlesmeht tsgnoma skool gnitfihs
.srae eniuqe llat sih fo spit etihw eht hguorht dehsup ti litnu drawpu kcen sih morf dellevart hsulb knip ehT
.setalp dna senalp
.rebmemer ot drah saw deneppah reven taht tneve na tub ,ysatnaf eht kcab erujnoc ot tseb sih deirt nairB
.drah os ti ni deveileb eh esuaceb ot dah tI
,nooM ooM elbaffeni eht
.uoy ekil I dna emit eht lla dnim ym no er’uoY
.ytinas s’nairB no gninaw saw driew fo gab dexim a gnieB  etoyoC triD yb ”gnimaerdyaD“   yojne esaelP
.pu stit tnew siht fi gnilaeppa erom hcum demees ecaf sih ni dessot edanomel morf ykcits gnieB
.gnineppah yllautca saw gnineppah saw tahw mrifnoc ot sdneirf sih sdrawot dekool eh erehw stniop lareves erew erehT
.wap sih evaw ot eciohc sih saw ti ekil leef neve t’ndid nairB esuaceb ffo yllatot eb dluow ti taht toN
.ecno tnew ylno eh tub
.koobeton sih otno gnidloh yldrawkwa pu dewohs flow eht nehw rethgual dim neeb dah elbat eht ta eerht ehT
.ecaf s’flow eht otni thgir pu mlap a tohs eh erofeb mih tuoba gniyrrulf thgilf ro thgif fo esnes a ,dehctiwt meht fo hcaE
.EP ot ffo dedaeh siuoL sa thguac eh lla saw liat dettops A
.elzzum sih fo ekahs gnitnioppasid a deviecer ylno eh tub
.esle enoyna ot nosirapmoc ni tcefrep os eb ot demees did siuoL taht gnihtyrevE
.dnim sih no sgniht tuo detrulb tsuj eh litnu semit lareves tuhs dna denepo wam siH
,srac dna spuc ekil sepahs otni derutcurts eb dluow smeoP
suoiruc tub tnatiseh elttil A
,oN“ .ekops nairB sa denetsil siuoL
.tuo ekats ot evah d’eh taht spohs eeffoc ynam taht t’nerew ereht dna
.dleif eht otno tuo dna mrofinu rieht otni degnahc ydaerla sdik tsom
,syaw elttil nwo rieht ni enif lla erew ASG eht ni ot decudortni neeb dah eh taht seno ehT
.steksabetsaw tseraen eht sdrawot staes rieht fo tuo decar seiceps lla morf stneduts sa detpure muinomednaP
.flow gnirettum eht ot noitnetta rieht gninrut ,dehcnilf mih dnuora stnedutS
.dnim ni yob eno ylno htiw gnignahc stneduts hguorht devaew eh
.rehto hcae morf tnatsid erom eb t’ndluoc yeht tey dna
,tuo gnillac dna mih dnuora gnikool erofeb nwod dna pu yltnappilf daeh sih deddon siuoL
,stpmetta deliaf elpuoc a retfA
dna krod a hcus ekil dekool eh
?yas ot detnaw eh tahw yas eh dluoc woH
,gnirumrum s’nairB etarelot ot demees syawla dah lakcaj eht elihW
.elbat eht morf yawa gnicar erofeb
.eno thgir eht dnuof dna efac yreve otni enog evah ll’eh
.yadhtrib sih no tfig a ekil ni ti koot eh dna
,mih no yldilos erew seye sih tuB
.lavorppasid ni daeh reh koohs dna deffocs
.tnemssessa riaf a eb ot demees taht dna
.knus worb s’siuoL yaw eht ebircsed ot drow tseb eht eb ylbaborp dluow denrecnoC
.ria eht otni deppilf mra sih
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
gnitlover yllufwa
,stneduts wef a ylno erew meht neewteB
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,neergreve citsalp eht dnuora yltnagele depparw sthgil samtsirhc eht gniwollof ylsseltsiL
,gniod saw eh tahw ro neeb d’eh erehw gniksa meht gnirongi
.uoy rehtob t’ndid taht epoh I
mih fo tnorf ni ksed eht dna gnikcap gnihsinif erew stnedutS
”.mraw yrev uoy speek ti ekil kool t’nseod ti hguoht ,semitemos raew uoy fracs neerg taht ekil I
,nwo sih otni peed gnirats smeg egnaro lufituaeb s’siuoL htiw ,erehT
.ti eb ot gniog saw sihT
,nirg a otni tilps elzzum sih sa gnirab sgnaf gnol ylsuoregnad esoht ,elims tahT
.seye sih denepo dna ria otni degnul nairB ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZB
.sselepoh ytterp ,llew ,saw ta saw rehcaet sih erehw morf sdrawkcab gnikroW
”?em thgif ot tnaw uoY“
gniworg elims diputs nwo sih gnileef ,dehctaw nairB
,wonk uoy ,hgu ,ekil eroM
.devom eh elihw strohs dna trihs-t sih no tup ot gniyrt tuoba delbmut eh dna drawkwa saw eH
.htmraw emos tuo htaerb ot elzzum sih revo meht deppuc dna edisni deppets eh
.swap owt sih ni ylmrif saw ti litnu koobeton eht htiw delbmuf dna noitnetta rof dehguoc nairB ,niaga gniyrT
daehrevo gnirevoh sretpocileh dna ,gninrutpu selbat ,gnihsams swodniw ,gnitimov
.detacitsihpos os tlef taht tneduts egnahcxe ngierof hcnerf a saw siuoL
,emit lanif eno ti denepo eh erofeb semit lareves nepo deppolf dna
,ffo tup yllatot ton tub ,delttaR
.yeknod eht dekees nairB
,puc eht dnuora depparw wap
,hguoht mih hctac dluow haraS
.airetefac eht fo srood elbuod eht tsap dehsup eh
,levon a gnidulcni
.daerd sti ni nairB gniflugne
.yldeticxe elzzum s’flow eht detfil lleb eht morf elgnij A
eson evitisnes s’enipul eht revo detfol osserpse dna klim demaetS
.noitseuq eniuneg a ekil tlef ti litnu liart sdrow wef tsal eht gnittel
.evirra ot dneirfyob erutuf sih rof detiaw nairB
.ynnuf s’tI .em tsurt ,on ,oN“ —nediw seye s’hateehc eht gniciton ,wap a detfil eH— ”yllautcA .eno thgir eht ot emac uoy litnu spohs tnereffid tuo gnikats
.sedis sih fo rehtie no mih sdrawot denrut ylthgils selzzum deciton eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,he ,ni em dniheb stis taht yob flow eht era uoY .olA“
.mih no segareveb toh
.dah meht fo tser eht naht retteb tuo krow ot demees eno siht ,tsael tA
.morf epacse ron kaerb t’ndluoc eh taht eno
.regnol yna noitcejer fo raef ni evil ot tnaw t’ndid eh ,oN
.ksed sih fo renroc eht no ti gnittis erofeb repap fo eceip nrot a no gnitirw dehsinif ehS
.teehs eht otno sdrow eht gnitcudnoc saw eh fi sa nep eht htiw llor dluow redluohs dna mra eritne sih
wap a dednetxe eH ”.nairB m’I
nettirw d’ehs lla saw ZZAPS
.mih morf noitcaer retteb a teg t’ndluoc ehs taht deyonna
hateehc eht naht erom mih erutrot ot od ot woh wonk dluow ehs taht gnihton saw erehT
niaga rekcol sih fo edisni regnol dnoces drawkwa na erats ot hguone ti thguof neht
,hateehc eht naht retrohs sehcni wef a s’taht flow a ,saw eh ereH
.mih dniheb sehcnul rieht gnisol elpoep raeh dluoc nairB noos
,mih deciton yeht nehw nwod deid rethgual riehT
,sdleif eht sdrawot tuo rehto hcae deklaw meht fo owt ehT
.moor eht fo sedis etisoppo no tsomla erew yeht ,wor emas eht derahs yeht hguohT
ro desserd ylluf s’eh litnu tiaw eh dluohS
nwot a fo gib taht t’nsaw tI
.ecnats sih ni ydaerla saw dna gnihcaorppa mih nees dah siuoL
”.rentrap yduts a dnim t’nod uoy fi pleh ruoy deen annog ylbaborp m’I ,yllautcA .od ew ,haeY“ .s’siuoL htiw ti degnahcxe eh sa eniuneg tlef llits
.ti thguac flow eht ,erehT
.koobeton sih otni ruop dluow hateehc eht taht gnihtyreve ees dluoc eh ,gnidnats fo sdnoces feirb esoht ni dna desucxe eb ot ksa d’eh ,hguoht revelc gnitteG
htaerb tsal eno koot eh
elzzum sih detlit nairB sa retal taht ediced dluoc yehT
.hsilgnE ni detnaw eh tahw dnuof eh erofeb ,hcnerF ni tuo emac tsrif ti
,rulb a ni gnitcaer sexelfer gninthgil sih
,elims eltneg a htiw meop sih dehsinif
,selbat eht neewteb deklaw eh sa tub
.dednetni eh naht ykahs erom tuo gnimoc erew sdrow dna tsaf os gnineppah lla saw sihT
,daeh sih ni deraperp dah eh taht sdrow eht fo llA
.meht gnitirw saw eh taht yaw eht devol eh
.srialce elttil ekil kool psalc rieht gnikam ,yltcefrep dednelb ruf wolley dna etihw ehT
.mih no erifkcab ot demees lla yeht
,aococ toh fo puc a saw swap nwo sih nI
.moor rekcol eht ni esle enoyna ro siuoL ton
.yrteop etirw uoy taht yaw eht ekil I“
.sllah eht hguorht nwod deklaw eh sa daeh sih tsniaga dedlof deniamer srae s’nairB ,nrow dna netaeB
”?em gniklats uoy erA“
,puorg dneirf nwo sih tsap thgir gniklaW
.seye sih erofeb thgir rehtegot emoc ot detrats nalp eht dna ti tog eh erehw derednow nairB
.yaw nwo sih ni tuo hcaer dluoc eh ,ebyam rO
.detrats eh nehw naht delffab erom tfel erew yeht
.niaga gnimaerdyad saw flow eht taht deciton evah tsum mih dnuora stneduts ehT
.llew og t’ndid taht ,lleW
tuhs deppalc elzzum
.eci eht kaerb ot gnitiaw ettal toh eht saw mih morf ssorca taes ytpme eht fo tnorf ni ylgnitivni degnarrA
.taefed ni dnuorg eht no toof reh depmats nooccar eht
.pu gnissem saw eh gniht ylno eht t’nsaw taht tub
.ssensuoires fo arua na mih evig ot thgit dediarb enam sih dna sessalg htiw roines a
.saw ti sa esac teksab a ydaerla saw eh dna gnikcarw evren os saw siht fo llA
,yltnatalb mih gnihctaw saw hateehc eht ,ereht tsomla saw eh taht emit eht yB .doog oN
,rettiwT no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac t'nsi eh nehw ,ohw
,yldiputs gnilims saw eH
,saw eh fi ,tey dna
.oot eno ekil tlef ylbaborp
.loohcs retfa tuo gnignah tuoba deklat dna srebmun degnahcxe yehT
.rekcins elttil a tuo tel eh
,flow eht otni kcab nward tog tsuj eh
.ti did eh sa redder dna redder gninrut dna nairB ta kcab gnicnalg morf pots t’ndluoc eh ,hguoht suovreN
,mih ni tseretni yna evah ot demees reven ohw ASG eht ni yeknod eht ,nitsuD
.gnissap ni don gnigdelwonkca na semitemos dna selims yoc sevlesmeht evig dluow yeht
,citanul a ekil kool mih edam tI
.daeh sih fo kcab eht gnihctarcs wap eno htiw deilper nairB
”.em ta gnikool uoy deciton I thguoht ,hu ,I“
,yas ot gnihtyna dnif ot eganam did eh nehW
.esle gnihtemos was nairB
.won ti gniod saw hateehc eht taht ees dluoc nairB
.srettum delffum sa tuo emac tsuj yeht ,derebmemer eh snoitrop eht kaeps ot detrats eh nehw
,htaerb a koot ,spil deppahc sih dekcil nairB ”.taht s’tI
,roolf eht tsniaga deggard seohs tnemec siH
.erif no tes neeb tsuj dah liat sih ekil raeppasid yob eht dehctaw eh
,evisnefed saw ecnats sih dna delkcirp saw ruf sih hguohT
.mih gnieye eb d’eh taht edih ot deknarc ylthgils elzzum sih htiw tsuj
yna evah t’ndid eh nehw gnittif erom saw hcnul taht dediced eh tub
”?elbat a erahs ot annaw uoy oD .haey ,hgU“
,ylgnignellahc gnaf emos erab ot kcab nward spiL
ni lla ,nehT .evol sih dna
.uoy ot ti evig dluoc I os ni klaw dluow uoy taht gnipoh tsuj flah a dna keew tsap eht rof ot tnew I pohs eeffoc yreve ta ettal a thguob yllautca I
,sresol fo kcap nwo sih htiw loohcs dnuora mih gnihctaC
,etoyoC triD yb ”gnimaerdyaD“
,fo kaeps ot strops on
.tops eht no dehsinav yletavirp siuoL ot kaeps ot tseuqer eht dna ,ekoj ykriuq sih
.nirg nwo sih yawa epiw ot elbanu
.tnecca hcnerf kciht yxes sih ni deksa eh ”?on ,htaM
.drawrof evom dluoc eh erofeb elpmaxe txen eht no etartnecnoc ot evah dluow eH
daeh sih ni sleehw ehT
.ssalc htam sih ni ksed sih ta gnittis llits saw eh dna dehsinif tsuj doirep tsriF
saw taht tahw erus t’nsaw
.thgil yttan s’dad sih no dezzub gnitteg dna deew gnikoms rof doog saw taht puorg dneirf a dna
.erutcel eht htiw pu hctac ot gniyrt erofeb ”.ffo ’ffE“
,gnineppah saw tahw tuoba desufnoc elttil a llits ,hateehc eht dna
,tuoba gniklat saw tnorfpu taog eht tahw tuo erugif ot delbmarcs eH !toohS
?knarp naciremA cissalc a sihT .ti teg I ,hO“
,dehsinif eh nehw dna
.denigami eh sa yltcaxe spets sih fo lla decarter eh ,pu gnidnatS .dekrow eno siht
rehtaew ot drah dna
.flesmih ta kcab neht dna flow eht sdrawot detniop eh ,ekops eh sA ”?em ekil uoY“
.melborp htam a tuo gnillif saw eh nehw etirw dluow eh woh susrev yrteop etorw eh taht yaw eht ,ekiL
”.nnH“ ,a tuo gnittel daetsni dna sdrow yas ot gnikool
.daeherof sih morf ekorb taews dna dehsulf srae sih ni etihw ehT
.repap reh ot gninruter erofeb mih ot tfig gnitrap reh saw etulas regnif elgnis A
.nrets gniniamer ,dias eh ”,seY“
?gnileef eb ot desoppus eh saw tahw tub
mih neewteb pag eht esolc ot sruoh koot ti ekil tlef ti
,riahc sih morf gnisir flow eht gnihctac hateehc eht ot ssentiw koot enoyrevE
.noissefnoc eht ni gnuh esuap A
,ekoms ta gnipsarg ekiL
,hguoht noitcennoc eht ekam ton ot gnimeeS
elbissop sa kciuq sa eb ot gniyrt ,segap eht hguorht deppilf eH
,hguoht dleif eht ot tog yeht sA
.evom yreve sih gnizylana seye leef dluoc eh
,yaw sih sreggad gnidnes nooccar ypperp a ,selyM haraS
.gninrom yreve ni thguorb eh ettal a ta gnippis saw eh
.ymmut tespu na tuoba nialpmoc ot eciffo s’esrun eht ot gninrut detalpmetnoc eh dna
.siuoL dniheb llaw eht tsniaga srekcol eht ta gnidnats saw
,citamard elttil a ,thgirlA
.etuc erew syob dna syob dekil eh taht wenk tsuj eH
.nooM ooM elbaffeni eht
,thgirla erew sdneirf siH
.flesmih gnignahc no sucof ot deirt dna rekcol sih ot kcab denrut nitsuD ,delzzaR .flow eht gnirimda
,slarehpirep sih fo tuO
.flow gnikool yzarc eht tuoba hcum gnikniht ton enil eht sdrawot deklaw hateehc eht
,elims gnilttesnu ylemertxe siht ni nezorf nairB tpek ssensuovreN
,hguoht pets lluf a teg yllautca dluoc eh erofeB
.tnew hateehc sih lleh eht erehw tuo erugif ot gniyrt dnuora daeh sih dekrej eh ,deiznerF .ytpme saw
.pu deird ecnis gnol dah dettolla saw eh ecneitap eht taht gniwonk
.mih fo tnorf ni thgir ksed eht ni gnittis saw siuoL ,lla retfA
,noil a saw ereht nehT
.loohcS hgiH potlliH ot kcab ecaep gnirb ot gnithgif
,daeh s’hateehc eht ot pu gnitnioP
.llew sa tsuj deviecer saw dna sag suoixon ekil ria eht ni detfaw tI
,gniyrc ,gnimaercs fo sdnuos eht htiw dellif emoceb dah ecalp eritne eht nooS
.tuo daeh dluoc eh erofeb hateehc eht ot resolc teg ot gnitpmetta tslihw esoht otni gnignahc dna sehtolc myg sih tuo gnillup erofeb rekcol eht otni meht deffuts eH
,sevlesmeht hsuh ot demees ydob tneduts eht fo lla ,tcaf nI
?dlrow elohw eht ni hateehc suoegrog tsom eht ot reffo ot evah nairB did tahw tub
daeh sih ni sleehw ehT
.ekahs elbmin a mih evag dna ylsuoituac ti koot
,nosrep tnereffid yleritne na yb dellortnoc gnieb saw eh ekil tlef llits tI
,srekcol fo wor eht nwod sfeirb eulb thgirb sih ni hateehc eht was eh nehw dna yltcefrep pu denil gnihtyrevE
.uoy knaht on tub ,uoy knahT“
.mih ta hgual dna tuo pop ot ecneidua emos rof dnuora dekool eH
,tseretnisid neddus eht yb kcaba nekaT ”?huh hu ,hO“
,loohcs erofeb hateehc eht hctac ot detnaw nairB .yrteop ta
.dnoces yreve suolucidir erom dekool snoisserpxe sih dna detsiwt elzzum sih ,gnilggurtS
wap sih yrt ot hguone tnedifnoc tlef eh
”,...tsuj dna uoy ta kool I semitemos ,tsuj ,taht s’tI“
?gnihtemos ro seissis era hcnerf eht lla esuac‘ dik hcnerf eht fo nuf ekaM
,ekops dna swap sih pu dleh eh
yrtemonogirT morf enilef raed yM
,mih gnihctaw neeb d’eH
.raf siht gnitteg tsuj tneps saw dah eh thguoht eh egaruoc eht fo llA
,nitsuD ”?noitanigami
,hguoht won flesmih fo erusnu elttil A
.edisni elihw esool fracs sih dellup eh nehw tsehc sih morf dedurtorp ruf fo tfut etihw duolc A
.srexob sih revo strohs eulb sih dellup flow eht sa mih gniyduts
.yawyna mih rof yldab dedne meht fo tsom dna eurt erew tuoba gnikniht neeb dah eh taht sgniht eht fo enoN
.wap s’hateehc eht fo dloh gnibbarg yltneg dna drawrof gnippets ,sreirrab eht hguorht tuc nairB
dna dnim ot emac ekoj eht fo stnemgarf ylnO
.snaej dna trihs sih ffo gnippir dna nepo rekcol eht gnigniws erofeb kcol sih otni noitanibmoc eht dehsur nairB
.kcaba nekat ,derettuts nairB ”?evah uoy ,hgu—I“
.troffe saw pets yrevE
.srae yffulf s’hateehc eht ni devideson dna ria eht otni tuo detaolf dah ti nehw naht daeh sih ni reinnuf semit evif ot ruof tsael ta saw yrots eht taht nrows dah eH
nairB	 ?rehtegot yag eb esaelp ew nac tuB
,llew sa klaw nairB gnihctaw neeb dah nitsuD
”,uoy deciton evah I“
.dekcuhcpu eh sa yllufemahs elzzum sih gnidih dna kcapkcab nwo sih fo dloh gnibbarg
.moorhtab a ot teg ot ecno ta lla srood airetefac eht hguorht gnizeeuqs deirt yeht sa rehto hcae revo derebmalc yehT
,thgir sgniht ekam ot ecnahc tsal enO
.mih gnissik ot tog reve d’eh tsesolc eht saw oiranecs siht ,yllautcA
,mih ekil tsuj roinuj a ,nitsuD
?eb ot tnaem reven erew yeht naem siht diD
.flesmih denethgiarts dna dnoces a rof yeknod eht ffo noitnetta sih koot nairB
?tnereffid yrev eb taht dluow os ,htaM saw ti ,hguoht
”uoy tuoba gnihtyreve ekil tsuj I ,kceH
.ksa ot derehtob dah sdneirf sih naht rehto enoyna taht ton