.hcum oot yrrow t'nod tub
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.emit hcnul ta seman ytsan mih dellac
,eson ym delknirw dna liat ym fo kcilf deyonna na evag I
!raor taht ot detcaer ew woh
.retsamdaeh ruo rof rood eht nepo ot
.ydal gnuoy a rof yllaicepse ,tnatropmi yrev era sdneirF !desaelp os ma I
,rethguaddnarg lufituaeb yM
.sessap suriv siht litnu tneitap eb ot deen uoy tub emit eht lla tnemtrapa eht ni yats ot ysae ton s'ti wonk I
.elbat nehctik eht no nwo ruoy fo loohcs a gnivah ekil tsomla—
eb ot uoy wonk I ydal eht ekil gnihtyna era uoy fi ,revewoH
,llaw dnuorgyalp eht no tas ew elihw sreppotsbog fo gab ym eta eW
ksed emas eht ta tas ew dna mih htiw etalocohc ym derahs I esuaceb tub
,araS raed ym ,lleW   "!ECIFFO EHT OT MEHT EKAT LLIW I GNIVAHEBSIM ENOYNA FO RAEH I FI dna tcepser htiw detaert eb ot si eh—"   ?derednow ew ,tahw s'eH .drawrof tniop ot moor eht ni rae
.loohcs fo tol a dessim eh os ,mih htiw og ot dah eh dna
.yad taht feihcrek ym togrof dna eson ynnur a dah I llacer I
,uoy ekil tsuj ,enin saw I nehw yad enO
.em gnillac si amdnarG ruoy sa ,ereh liame ym hsinif llahs I
.sruf lla tsomla saw loohcs ruo tub ,neht kcab saw taht gniht gib a tahw dnatsrednu t'ndluow uoy ,woN    .namuh a saw eH
.evif erew ew ecnis dneirf tseb ym saw eh dna laof a saw kcirreD
.revetahw ro ,esroh ,flow ,namuh ,ybbat yeht eb—
VT eht revo otohp ym ecalper ot gniog s'ehs doog os si em fo gniward ruoy syas amdnarG ruoY
.noitnetta fo ertnec eht ta eb ot ecin saw ti tub ,ecaps rellams a otni sgniht dna skoob ym evom ot dah I os ,ksed ym ta tis ot nwod mih del reveehC ssiM
.llew os flesruoy nialpxe ot dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.nepo rood moorssalc eht tfel yeht hguoht ,sgniht pu-nworg
,sserpxe uoy ot ti pihs
.mih ta kcab ylsuovren dekool lla ew dna
elbaulav yllaer ton erew yeht ,thgirlA
,araS
!seussit elbasopsid ruoy gnirb syawlA
egaruoc lufthguoht emas eht htiw egnellahc hcae teem lliw uoy—
nwot ruo ni syob namuh wef yrev erew erehT
.detca uoy pu-nworg woh dna
.srehto fo nuf gnikam yojne dna leurc eb nac nerdlihc emos ,araS ,tuo dnuof uoy sA
!tol a gnuts tI
,em ekil ybbat rehtona eb dluow eh depoh I
,sepirts ym fo esuaceb ,'regiT'
.enod dah eitnua ym tahw  gniypoc
… uoy htiw eb dna enalp a no poh ll'ew nwod elttes sgniht ecnO
par ehT .rood moorssalc ruo ot emac kconk a
si yrots s’yadot dna
.setamssalc ruoy dna loohcs eht wonk ot gnitteg emit trohs a hcus dneps ot tog ylno uoy yrros m’I
ereht niamer lliw ti dna
dedda I ,od ot em dlot dah eitnua ym tahw gniod
ll'ew yad gib ruoy rof ht71 yaM yb revo teg t'nac ew fi esimorp I
.dnekeew eht ta lausu sa retupmoc eht no lla uoy htiw tahc llahs ew dna
.ruf on evah yeht fi ro ,ruf rieht ni sruoloc eht ro ,sreksihw rieht htgnel tahw
.em ediseb tis ot evah dluow yob wen ehT
,enizagam nocorhtnA eht ni deraeppa sah krow siH
.etamssalc wen ruo decudortni neht
.eromyna em ot klat t'noD"
ecaf nrets sih htiw moorloohcs eht dnuora dereep eh yad ralucitrap siht nO
'godhctaW' :mailliW rof emankcin a edam I
!gnuoy os eno rof citsitra yrev era uoY
,gniht thgir eht yltcaxe gniod saw I gniveileB
.rehcaet sih fo dnik saw I ekil tlef I .devol I hcihw
hctaw ew elihw macbew ruoy fo tnorf ni ti nepo nac uoy neht
.enod htrae no krow sih redisnoc dna meht fo 563 evah ll'eh tniop emos tA ."selaT droW 563" meht gnillac
,ylreporp loohcs ot og dna nwod elttes dluohs eh detsisni rehtomdnarg siH
.ydaerla dneirf-tseb wen a edam uoy yppah os m'I ,oslA
.mailliW detaert I ekil enoemos detaert reve uoy fi retal leef dluow uoy woh tuoba kniht
.ytiniffA ruF no puorg "tpmorP yadsruhT"
.em tespu ti dna edur ylerar saw eitnua yM
em tcelloc ot etag loohcs eht ot emac eitnua ym ,dneirf ym emaceb mailliW retfa owt ro keew a
,sussateM yb ”araS raeD“ saw sihT
gnorw os saw txen did I tahw ,araS
!llet em ekam t'nac uoy—
,dnuorgyalp eht ni sreidlos dna seips gnieb ta deyalp eW !ti devol eH
,taht ekil enoyna truh reven uoy niatrec ekaM
.flesym rof sekac dna sdaerb ruoy tuo yrt ot tiaw t'nac I dna
.meht htiw erusaelp dna yoj hcum os erahs uoy esuaceb laiceps yrev era sdneirf tseB
,wonk t’nod uoy sdik rehto htiw flesruoy rof pu dnats ot drah yrev s'tI
,taoc ym fo eveels eht no eson ym depiw I ,pmacs a etiuq gnieB
.meht wonk neve t'ndid ehS
,edisni emas eht era elpoep taht ,araS raed ,rebmemer syawlA
.devil ew erehw tuoba gniklat
esle enoyna naht retteb era uoy
.ydaerla nommoc ni tol a dah I dna mailliW thguoht I
;dneirf tseb ruoy ekil ,doog yrev eb lliw emos
.rettahc ysion ruo hsuhs ot yawrood eht ni deraeppa daeh s'reveehC ssiM ,ylper dluoc eh erofeB
.yhw wonk t'ndid I tub ,ti tuoba debrutsid tlef I dna yad eht fo tser eht rof mih ees t'ndid I
?em rof ekil saw sloohcs gnignahc tahw em deksa uoy rebmemer uoY .oga gnol
,araS raed ym ,yldaS
.emoh nar yllausu I os ,loohcs eht morf setunim fo elpuoc a ylno
koobyrots a ni fle na ekil tsomla dekool taht ecaf gnitseretni na dna
.namuh a si mailliW"
.lliH thgirB ni rehtomdnarg sih htiw evil ot nwot otni devom tsuj sah mailliW
,reiruoc sterces tnatropmi na eb dluow I erehw
.emankcin a dah loohcs ruo ta enoyrevE
,desimorp I sa eceipeltnam eht no drac ruoy decalp ev'I
.uoy htiw yrots siht erahs ot hsiw I yhw nosaer eht si siht dna ,taht ekil tuo krow ton did ti
,dnalerI fo tsew dliw eht ni desaB
uoy fo duorp os m’I yhw ees nac uoy os erom elttil a uoy llet ll’I kniht I
.os ssel elttil a eb thgim emos hguoht
.apdnarG gnivol ruoY
dneirf tseb ruoy dna—ereht stneduts eht em sllet osla ehS
”araS raeD“:yojne esaelP
htnom tsal ssalc wen ruoy ot uoy decudortni rehcaet ruoy enigami I sa tsuj ,enoyreve ot mih decudortni dna
.mih fo deracs lla erew ew dna ,lesaew niht ,nrets a ,llat yrev saw eH
nuf taerg saw tI
.ecalp sih dloh ot regnif sih esu ot dah dna duol tuo gnidaer ta wols elttil a saw eH .mih dekil I
moorssalc ym morf sdik rehto eht fo emos neht tuB
,em dna amdnarG sa hcum sa ti ot drawrof gnikool erew uoy wonk I
,llems namuh ecin taht dah mailliW
.eitnua ym htiw ,lliH thgirB ni devil osla I .dethgiled saw I ".lliH
.dneirf ym tsol I woh dna
.evitcnitsid yrev saw par-par-a-
.pu edam ew semankcin wen yllis emos dna ssalc ruo ni enoyreve fo tsil eht saw dah ew lla—
,reveehC ssiM ,rehcaet ruO
,neht kcab dlot saw I os ,taht ekil yllaer t'nod slriG
yhpargotohp sih weiv dna
,erew ew sa retsamdaeh ruo fo deifirret sa tsuj saw reveehC ssiM kniht I
.tnelis tnew moor eritne eht
,lleW ?uoy t’nod ,remmus tsal morf snilloC .srM dna .rM rebmemer uoy ,sruobhgien rood-txen ruO
.efil rof sdneirf emaceb dna pu werg htob I dna mailliW kniht thgim uoy niatrec osla m'I
.taht saw taht dna
.yawa mih devom dna
,t'now I esimorp em edam sah amdnarG ruoy yawynA
kniht ot nigeb reve uoy fi enim fo yrots elttil siht tuoba kniht ot uoy ekil dluow I esuaceb ,yldnoceS
,yltsriF .eno elttil teews ym ,snosaer eerht rof uoy ot yrots siht llet I
yreve desuac esuap lausunu s'retsamdaeh ruO   "—si eh—eH .yadot etamssalc wen a evah uoy" ,decnuonna eh ",nerdlihC"   .parts rehtael sih fo deracs sa t’nsaw ehs spahrep hguoht
,rehtie devirra tey ton dah rehtomdnarg s'mailliW
.railucep  saw tI .lla ta gnihton—
.loohcs wen ruoy ni skeew fo elpuoc tsrif ruoy tuoba wonk em tel yddad ruoY
,mih morf yawa yats ot em deredro ehs tub ,su ekil tsuj erew snamuh taht nialpxe ot deirt I ".ytrid
.dneirf wen ym tuoba deksa dna reh fo tnorf ni em doots ehs
.ereh evil ot gniog saw eh os
".snamuh ytrid ot klat t'ndluohs seibbaT
yllanoisacco—taht uoy wohs ot
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,lliw syawla dna ylraed
.htnom txen rof tisiv ruo lecnac ot dah ew emahs a hcus s'tI
.llahs reve I kniht t'nod I
tseraed yM   .0202 ,01 lirpA   sussateM yb
,t'nevah I tuB .sah eh epoh I
".ytrid er'uoy dna namuh er'uoY
dias I tahw tuoba kniht I nehw das os leef llits I
.egaugnal tnereffid a evah ro ,ecalp tnereffid a ni evil ro ,tnereffid kool yeht esuaceb ylno
.ksed txen eht ta gnittis yob eht ot yldeticxe deksa I
.meht wonk yllaer t'nod yeht esuaceb tub
!meht sees amdnarG erofeb edih tsum I taht em rof staert emos ni kaens ot meht deksa I dna ,gnippohs ruo ffo deppord tsuj evah snilloC .srM dna .rM
.dam reh gnitteg ksir ot gniog ton m'I dna
,uoy htiw tsenoh yrev eb ot dna
!thgirf htiw flesmih tew hsaN sumaeS kniht I
.yad lla emoh ta lla er’uoy elihw
,yltnatropmi tsom dna ,yltsaL
.llew dna efas htob era I dna amdnarG taht wonk meht tel dna ,yddad dna ymmom ot evol ruo lla yevnoc oD
,ni deppets eh nehW
.em htiw etag eht ta gnitiaw saw eh os
!taht ekil semag htiw tnemyojne hcum sa tsuj teg uoy niatrec m'I—
.deneppah tahw tuoba nettogrof evah thgim eH
,loohcs ta kcab ,yad txen yrev ehT
.llah myg eht sdrawot ffo nar dna yrc ot detrats eH
.riahc eraps a htiw ksed a ta gnittis tneduts ylno eht saw I desilaer neht I
.sretupmoc ruoy no emit eht lla rehtegot tahc ehs dna uoy dias ymmom ruoY
.dnuora saw eh nehw feihcsim yna ot pu teg ot ton luferac erew syob eht lla os ,mih htiw parts sih deirrac syawla retsamdaeh ruO
,emoh dehcaer ew nehW
.sruf yltsom saw taht loohcs a morf gnivom er’uoy nehw yllaicepse
.loohcs ruo tfel mailliW ,retal skeew owT
.ksed ym nopu ereh pu depparw lla si tfig yadhtrib s'rethguad-dnarg etiruovaf ruo ,sey dna
ssucsid ot rodirroc eht otni tuo tnew spu-nworg owt ehT
uoy evol amdnarG dna apdnarG ruoy ,traehteews ,rebmemeR
.delknirw eson reh dna ecaf reh dessorc kool ynnuf a
.sussateM ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb ”araS raeD“
.loohcs ruf enilniam a ni namuh a rof etuc fo dnik tub
,rehtie mailliW wonk yllaer t'ndid I
.uoy fo duorp os m'I yas tsum dna  syad tsrif ruoy no detaert erew uoy yaw eht tuoba draeh osla I ,seY
.gnivahebsim thguac yeht enoyna kcams dluow neht kcab srehcaet tub ,siht eveileb ton thgim uoY
saw enim eveileb uoy dluoW(
!drac s'raey txen dnes uoy litnu—reve sa—
,retal sraey ytxis ,won nevE .mailliW truh I woh rof emahs leef syawla lliw I
gnihton dias ehs dna
!degnahc s'taht kniht I maet reccos ruoy ta gnikool hguoht
esirprus eht niur ot gniog ton llits m'I tuB
,yob yna rof emankcin taerg a—
,eb nac spu-nworg ylno sa suoires sa gnikool ,dias ehs ",hpesoJ"
.nosaer on rof truh peed esuac nac gnikniht tuohtiw sgniht yas oT
,uoy rof ecneirepxe wen gnizama na neeb sah siht erus m'I
kcab og dluoc I hsiw dna
.dnuos a ekam ot derad taht su fo yna dehsuhs dna
eht fo trap sa kcab emit emos gnitirw detrats sussateM
.sehsiw mraw ruoy dna drac yadhtrib lufituaeb ym rof uoy knahT
.elpoep rehto naht retteb leef meht sekam ti esuaceb gnorw era straeh rieht ni wonk yeht sgniht eveileb dna
.syad tsom did ew sa tsuj ,reidlos a ekil detulas dna "!ris ,noissim rof ydaer godhctaW" dias
.won rof hguone si taht ,yawynA   .araS
srehtaew lla ni ssarg eht ni edistuo llabtoof yalp dluow ew ,rebmemeR
!taerg os tsuj s’taht
,sesicrexe gnidaer htiw tuo mih pleh ot em deksa reveehC ssiM
,syad loohcs nwo ym fo emos derebmemer I ,taht tuoba ymmom htiw ekops I retfa ,wonk uoY
)!deracs sa t'nerew uoy teb I hguoht(
,tsrif eht sa doog sa ton si puorg rehtona kniht elpoep fo puorg eno nehw sneppah yllausu tI
,noonretfa ydniw dna yniar enO
.dah ew nuf taerg eht dna mailliW tuoba lla reh dlot I
.truh ylbirret dekool eh dna elap tnew ecaf siH
.ekatsim yb retnirp sih no yllanoisacco dna ,4 .loV gnaF ni
tol a dellevart dad sih esuaceb saw taht em dlot eH
neeb evah uoy gnidnatsrednu dna lufpleh woh tuoba yddad dna ymmom morf raeh ot dethgiled m'I
.hcum os ti ot drawrof gnikool erew uoy wonk I
amdnarG dna ymmom ruoy ekil hcum os—
dneirf ym detaert I woh tuoba lufwa leef llits I
.gnorw saw gnihtemos wenk I os ,kcilf ot detrats liat reH
... s'eH .mih htiw gniyalp eb ton dluohs uoY
.snamuh erew yeht esuaceb ylno elpoep s'mailliW no nwod dekool eitnua yM
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,gnorw yrev eb nac spu-nworg—
,teiuq eb ot su dlot dna denruter reveehC ssiM ,yllautnevE
.emit tluciffid siht ta
,ecaf rieht epahs tahw rettam on
,'ecidujerp' dellac si sihT
detsat s'ehs tseb eht era slliks gnikab ruoy syas ymmom ruoY
redluohs sih no wap reh tup reveehC ssiM sa
.ereht era ew fi sa tsomla—
.ytterp yrev saw ehs thguoht I  dna ssenoil a saw ehS
.dehsulb ehs dna pu werg I nehw reh yrram d'I taht ssalc ni ecno reh dlot I
.gnikool t'nsaw rehcaet eht nehw mih htiw etalocohc ym fo emos derahs I
.eromyna uoy htiw yalp ot dewolla ton m'I ,mailliW"
.swap ym fo hcae no parts rehtael a morf skcams xis dah I semit ynam dna legna on saw rehtafdnarg ruoY
.yesaC mailliW si siht" ,dias ehs ",syoB"
.I saw sa ,uoy htiw desaelp yrev saw rehcaet ruoY
enigami nac uoy
,tik a saw I nehW
ssendnik etaciled dna
deifirret dekool eH
,noitatuper lufwa dna repmet kciuq sih htiw
!daetsni reh yrram dluohs I taht ylthgir dediced rehtomdnarg ruoy ,yletanutroF
.loohcs eritne ruo ni owt ro eno ylno dna
)!yerg erom dna edalamram ssel m'I won fi neve
.snamuh yltsom era—
.od reve reven dluow uoy wonk I gnihtemos
.sterces elbaulav ruo gnitcetorp ,reciffo ytiruces godhctaw eht eb dluow mailliW dna
,ten.ytiniffaruf no
.niaga godhctaW eht mailliW ,morf draeh ro ,was reven I
.meht htiw erahs uoy
.rood ruo ot thgir meht pord dna erots eht ta keew hcae seirecorg ruo tcelloc yeht
:secneirepxe wen lufrednow htiw uoy edivorp dna ,araS ,sweiv gnitseretni emos uoy evig lliw erutluc namuh tuoba erom gninraeL
reh ot mailliW decudortni yletilop I
.taht retfa moor eht fo kcab eht ta hcneb a ta nwo sih no ylteiuq tas eH
!elpoep lufrednow hcuS
.won em ekil nam dlo na ylbaborp si mailliW
sgnitirw sih daer nac uoY
sruobhgien dna sdneirf rieht ot dnik gnieb era elpoep ynam os wonk ot ylevol s'tI
.gniticxe saw tahT
,sdik rehto ekil t'nod yeht esuaceb ton s'tI
moorssalc ruo ssorca dehsad ehs sa riahc reh morf decnuob tsomla
.slrig eht rof elbmut dna hguor oot eb dluow syob ew taht thguoht spu-nworg eht kniht I
devil I .allerbmu reh rednu emoh em gnirb dna
.slrig rof eno dna syob rof loohcs eno saw ereht
!niaga deraeppasid ehs nehw syob ydwor gnieb ot kcab tnew ew esuaceb sseltniop saw tI
.tseraed ym ,llew uoy sdnif liame siht epoh I
,mih was eitnua ym nehW
!emit eht lla swap s'amdnarG rednu gnitteg em ,ecalp eht dnuora gnirettup dna sroodni gniyats er'eW
,llew ,krow rieht od yeht elihw enilno sessalc ruoy htiw gniunitnoc era dna tsil serohc nwo ruoy edam ev'uoy taht gniraeh dnA
.krap eht ot gnilcyc og ro ,gnag a trats ebyam dluoc ew os
.ti rebmemer dna noitnetta esolc yrev yap ot uoy tnaw I
.moc.sussatem no ro
!daetsni ereht erutcip ruoy tup dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ssalc erofeb em ot pu emac mailliW
"?kcirreD ,eb ll'eh kniht ahctahW"
.t'nac I tub ,retteb ti ekam dna
enilno rehcaet ruoy htiw snossel od dna retupmoc ruoy no emoh morf krowloohcs ruoy lla od ot nuf eb tsum ti ,llitS
ylsuoixna mih dnuora dettilf reveehC ssiM
deneppah tahw fo draeh rehtaf sih taht retal tuo dnuof I
,noitcif-orcim detimil-drow no neek ylralucitrap si eH
.daeh sih no riah der dna selkcerf lla—
.yad taht eulg ekil em ot kcuts eh
,uoy ot evol ym lla htiW
.yddum yrev ssalc ot kcab emoc dna
.dlrow eht revo lla elbuort fo tol a sesuac ti dna