,ereh mih teg dluow gnirehtaG eht cigaM tuoba sekoj gnikam thguoht reven  ohw
yawhgih eht no tuo
”degnartsE denrecnoC raeD“
.mraw em htepeek ti ,llafniar eht dnA llafniar eht ot ecaf ym nrut ll’I
.dniw eht htiw ereht tuo erehwemos eB reverof dna
?od naidisbo eht tahw swonk ohW
.reh dniheb si liat esohw
,floWcaM boR si
.rewsna ym si
.enohp eht pu kcip ot emit on ev’I .won efil ym era
erehwyreve evil I
.eripsni ot rae na rof stiaw ti dnA ,deretsam sah eno on taht cisum si erehT
.dniheb yawhgih eht evael ll’I
.enod erew dna leuf fo tuo nar yehT
.drac a em tnes uoy deciton I
:nwo I taht eno ylno eht s’tI
. .reh dniheb si liat esohw
.drah os si emit eht gnidnif tuB ,rewsna na gnitcepxe er’uoy wonk I
.mrah on em od lliw yeht ,sniar ehT
og t’nac I ecalp eno eht dnA
,em ees reven ll’uoy hguoht nevE
saw sihT      .emoh yllanif
.nwonk tey sah kcolc namuh on tahT
.oot naidisbo gninetsilg dnA revlis fo dna
,nmutua emos fo dne eht ta ,ebyam dnA
—yawhgih eht no erehwemos meht tfel I
floWcaM boR yb meop a
.liameciov a em tfel uoy taht was I
.aes eht otni lla sroloc stI gnipeets dna gnittes eb lliw nus eht erehW
,gnitiaw edistuo stsohg eht dna sdog ehT
nodnaba em evah dluow
meop s’yadot dnA
,dfloWcaM boR yb meop a
.evivrus ot od ot dah ecno I tahW rebmemer uoy kniht t’nod I kniht I
eb ll’I erehw s'tahT
.eugnot ruoy morf etsat eht lla esol uoy dnA gnizeerf morf eno peek tonnac seil tuB
,teerts eht ni toofrednu seiks ehT
.gnivom seil eht peek t’ndluoc I dnA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.laeh dlog ehT
.emoh emoc ot ecnahc a rof egnahcxe nI
.nwot nettogrof yreve nI yella yreve nwod eb lliw I dnA
dlog fo selppa s’erehT
.seil yrassecen eht lla dlot I
—enola ereht tuo llits ylbaborp er’yehT
allerbmu ruoy deen ton lliw I dnA
—seert naht rellams era sniatnuom erehW stserof detnecs-nus ni stesnus ehT
.sehsiw tnarg revlis ehT
.remmus eht ot eybdoog yas ll’I
.erif dah sah nam naht regnol roF detsal sah ssenllits esohw snedrag era erehT  .emoh si
.nwod nrot erew spohs dlo erehw stol eht nI esirnus eht ni tuo eb lliw I oS
uoy eseht llA
”degnartsE denrecnoC raeD“  :yojne esaelP
thgindim dnoyeb sruoh eht eht ni sruoh era erehT
.emoh emoc t’ndluoc I taht wenk I
sgniht eseht fo llA
.draobpuc kcab reppu eht ni devil I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
em rof gnitiaw eb lliw pihs A
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb uoy rof daer
,”degnartsE denrecnoC raeD“ dellac
,pihs eht ekat ll’I
.gniklaw tog dna dnuora denrut I nehT
,diarfa m’I ,taht dnA