”?eno-yb-eno meht yrrac nac ew ebyaM“
.ereht erew ew tegrof ot demees ehs ,ti ta gniratS ”…ynihs oS
”!nooccar a ton s’tahT“
”!?enutrof llams a htrow slamina dnomaid fo hcnub a htiw“
.deb god ym ni pu kcab delruc I
.yvaeh osla saw tI
,peej a saw erehT
.gnireviuq slliuq
,em esucxe ll’uoy fi ,woN“
,gnidliub eht fo edis kcirb eht pu delbbarcs dna ,dias stoeD
.dooh eht ffo toof reh koot dna
.elosnoc eht fo retnec eht ni ti no detnirp ”tratS“ sdrow eht dah taht nottub der a saw erehT
”.em rof kcab gnimoc rof uoy knahT“
”?ereh llits uoy era yhw nehT“
”taR eht ni dnomaiD“
,emag rac s’ynnuS ni sa tsaf sa t’nsaw deeps mumixam s’rac ehT
,eb ot desu goP ekil
,edis eht morf desivrepus stoeD
”.dessap sah mrof latrom ruoy litnu
.tuo drow eht werd xaM ”…kkkcuuuF“ ”.eineg a rO
.eloh eht hguorht pu enihs ot kcab emac neht dna ,tfel
.ti enod d’yeht woh tuo erugif ot gniyrt
.neercs eht ta detniuqs eH
won rof ereh yats lliw I
”,snooccar tsuj ylbaborP“
.deb ot ffo em tnes neht
”.rac yawa-teg a dedeen ew dna ,tar eht evas ot kcab og ot dah I“
,nwod gnidils pu dedne I dna ,skcirb eht sa suorop sa ton saw flehs yalpsid ehT
,tuo sdrow eht ecrof ot elba ylerab ,htuom sih dekrow eh ”…snooccar
skcirb eht ni snoisserped eht otni swalc ym demmaj I
,kcurt eht no tas sabanraB
”.eno siht ekat ll’I“
”.gnilaets erom on em esimorp tub
yella eht nwod su del stoeD
”,erots euqitna eht fo kcab eht si sihT“
”?tar ,uoy eerf ew nac woH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.hgis a htiw meht derewol neht dna
,eno tsellams eht pu dekcip rettalC
pots a ot derrihw naf eht fo dnuos ehT
.em gniyrrac xaM tuohtiw regnol tol a demees ereht revo klaw ehT  2 fo
.seod ti ,seY“ .dias xaM
.eutats eht pord em gnikam ,swap ym deppals kciredoR ”—ussamal a s’tI .tar a ton s’ti syas tI“ ,detalsnart I
,deksa ehs ”?ti laets uoy did ,goP“
.slliuq reh fo eno otni eson ym dekop yltnedicca dna kcab s’rettalC ot esolc tog I tniop eno tA
,tirips naidraug esuoh a eb tsum ussamal A
.snoitcurtsni s’ynnuS morf aedi lareneg eht wenk I tuB
.em dekcirp dah ti erehw gnillaf doolb fo pord a
”,goP ,syas ti gnihtyna ot netsil t’noD“
”,ni yaw ruo s’tahT“
.deb reh yb rac eht dekrap I
.emit siht ussamal eht draeh yeht sseug I
.dnuof dah sabanraB tahw ot revo dehsad I sa
.xaM ,hctins a eb t’noD“
.odnoc s’ynnuS sdrawot kcab evord dna niaga rac eht detrats I
.kcolb eht delcric I sa weiv otni emac sehsurb ylggarcs dna sllaw kcirb krats tub gnihtoN
.srehto eht htiw esrup eht ni ti deffuts I ”.ereh fo tuo teg ot evah llits eW
swap tnorf owt ym neewteb ti depsalc I
.em htiw ereh segam owt evah I ,oS .ereht iH“
,bmilc ot deirt dna htuom reh ni ti tup ehS ”.ti yrT“
,ffo llef sgniht emos dna ,delbbow kcar ehT
.tnemeticxe htiw gnipoohw
.snooccar eht naht reyarg saw ruf ym
,ereht erew evlewt lla emit eht yB
”.hud ,ynihs er’yeht esuaceB“
.ecnartne s’odnoc eht ot pu derettup ew sa nwonk flesti edam melborp ehT
.eutats eht otni kcab dna
.enohp sih no erutcip a em dewohs kciredoR
.eno yb debbor teg yeht thgin taht neht dna adnap der a htiw yadretsey ereht ni saw I
ot dah eW .lortnoc doog ylriaf dah I
”.seye wolley emos was I kniht I dnA“ .dias eh
kcirb eht fo erutxet eht otni swalc sih kcuts sabanraB ”.siht ekiL“
.detcepxe I naht erom dehgiew erugif ehT
.taes eht ni nwod gniknirhs ,dias I ”,laets enifeD“
pag eht hguorht delggirw yeht
,pu doots eh sa htaerb sih rednu dias xaM ”,od uoy fi rO“
”.daeh sti no gniht taht dah tI“
”.tey ti eerf t’nod ew fi retteb s’ti kniht I
.dewollof su fo tser ehT .deraeppasid dna
.taes ym dniheb knurt eht no dehcrep sabanraB dna
,ereh pu tsud eht dna ,em no debbur dah snooccar eht yalc eht neewteB
.sdrawkcab delbmarcs dna depley kciredoR dna xaM
,niaga peelsa llaf dluoc I erofeb tuB
.em sa noisulcnoc emas eht ot gnimoc yltnerappa
.kcab srae ym gnitsiwt ,reh ta dekool I ”?woH“ .dias stoeD ”?su rof ti nepo ot snamuh eht teg ew fi tahW“ .ediw seye
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.pleh rof gnillac er’yeht kniht I
.revo emac dna melborp eht was stoeD
.eciov dehctip-rehgih a dah eno sihT
”,ffo tnew mrala gniliec ehT“
.em ot enil eht nwod ti dessap dna ti thguac nooccar pot ehT
.uoy eveileb I ,thgirlA“
”taR eht ni dnomaiD“
.tar dnomaid eht gnidloh ,deb ym ot txen roolf eht no deggel-ssorc nwod delttes dna dehgis xaM
2 traP ,ressoR naoR yb
,egarag gnikrap tnemesab eht ot nwod ecnartne ehT
.hteet dehcnelc hguorht dias eh
”.ti elots uoy emussa ot gniog m’I
.meht deidaets dna revo nar I dna stoeD litnu ,gniyaws rewot eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.efil ot dekrej rac eht dna rotarelecca eht no wap ym nwod demmals I
.sdraug namuh yna ffo eracs dluoc ehs taht tnedifnoc os saw rettalC rednow oN
.eert ’stoeD dehcaer ew nehw detnioppasid tsomla saw I  #  .daor eht nwod
.moor eht fo tuo depmots dna pu doots xaM
.emit a ta eno rac eht otni slamina dnomaid eht tfil
,sdrawkcab delbmuts dna
,taog ,yeknom ,regiT
,dias namow eht ”?…tahW“
.aedi siht htiw gniog saw stoeD erehw gniees ,deddon ehS
”,adnap der a tuoba gnihton ,snooccar denoitnem ylno swen ehT
,dnuora rac eht denrut I dna
.reh dewollof srepleh tnelis eerht reH
.su gnisahc saw draug rehtieN
”,ussamal a m’I ,tar a ton m’I“
,muinomadnaP deR fo rohtua ,ressoR naoR yb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,em ot txen taes regnessap eht ni tas stoeD
.leehw eht htiw reetS
,rood tnorf eht raen pots ot emac I
,swap tnorf rieht ni hcae eno yrrac dluoc snooccar ehT
did syawla ynnuS ekil tsuj ”!ssa-kcaj ,evird ot nraeL“
”,pleh dluoc taht gnihtemos dnuof I“
”.emirc eht htiw flesruoy tcennoc dna ti htiw drawrof emoc ot ton retteB“
.ereht tpek erugif dnomaid a ni deppart si enoemos tuo dnuof goP erehw
.em ot railimafnu saw drow taht tub
.ecaf sih revo sdnah sih tup dna em deppord eH
,esrever ot woh tuo erugif ot tnemom a em koot tI
.meht denioj I dna rettalC sa dias ehs
,yeknom ,taog ,regit ,nekcihc ,tibbar ,esroh ,ekans ,hu ,erew slamina ehT“
.htreb ediw a rettalC evag srehto eht deciton I
.tar eht no neeb d’I sa desucof ,reilrae noitnetta gniyap neeb t’ndah I
.swap ym tuo dleh dna pu tas I
”,nroh rac a ekil dednuoS“
.hguoht ,thgir s’goP“
”?won gnihtyna gniyas ti sI“
ti erehw slliuq reh otni yawa ti dekcut ehS
,eno tsesolc eht dehsup eh
,nuf rof ereh t’nsaw I
daeh ym dnuora delriws tar yltsohg ehT
.sgel s’nam eht rof thgiarts dedaeh slliuq s’rettalC
taes regnessap eht otni revo debmilc eh sa dias sabanraB
.rellorts a ni dnuora em hsup meht tel dluow I ebyaM
.em ta derats xaM
.su ot pu gnimoc ,dias rettalC ”,edis rehto eht no gnitiaw era snamuh ehT“
”.nooccar a saw I skniht potpal eht neve ,eeS
.devom ehs sa detnilg dna derettilg
.reh dnuora elcric a ni luah reh degnarra ehs sa dias stoeD
.revo ti gninrut ,ti ta nwod dekool dna desuap I
”.worromot ni ti gnirb dna erehwemos ti edih nac I ebyaM
.ecafrus eht ssorca devom neehs kcils lio ehT .dias eutats eht
.sdaeh rieht koohs meht fo htoB
.dlohserht eht revo tnew ew sa elttil a gnicnuob
.efil ym lla gnibmilc neeb d’I ekil tlef I
.gab eht gnikcik ,dias I
,rood eht tuo tohs ew sa ediw seye
.serauqs etihw ytsud htiw latem fo dirg a dehcaer ew yllautnevE
.teprac eht otno dellor dna
.emoc d’ew yaw eht kcab evord dna
,tool eht htiw detiaw snooccar eht erehw ot erutinruf eht dnuora gnirevuenam retfA
.gnikool em was eh nehw pu sbmuht a em evag eH
.ti wonk I .ecilop eht morf llac a teg ot gniog m’I
,ylenol dna deppart eb ot ekil s’ti tahw wonk I tub“
.evom ot elggurts xaM nees d’I taht sgniht latem gnikool-yvaeh esoht fo eno saw rood kcab ehT
.srehto eht htiw gab eht ni kcab ti gnittup ,dias I
.delley I ”!tep a toN“
.pag eht ni deraeppa ecaf namuh a dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.eucser ot tar a dah I
,nepo dekcarc rood ehT .peeeeeeb-peeb-peeB .peeb-peeB .peeeeeB .peeB .snrettap ni nroh eht gnipeeb nuf dah I
.evord ehs nehw did ynnuS ekil leehw gnireets eht fo retnec eht desserp I
”,tar eht gnipeek er’ew sseug I“
.em ta dekool dna ,dias xaM
xaM ot txen teprac eht no nwod tas kciredoR
.esruoc fo ,ytisoiruC“
,nepo gnipag htuom reh
,hguone gib saw eloh eht ecnO
,pu dellac rettalC dna
.eutats eht em dednah xaM ”.ti ees em teL“
.gnikrims ,daeh reh koohs ehS ”.yhtlif er’uoY“
wap a htiw ti deppals I
”.sabanraB si gnisseug m’I taht lerriuqs a dnA“
”,ti gnisserp peeK“
.sabanraB ot pu dellac I ”,nwod meht ssoT“
.thgilhsalf rieht deppord dna demaercs namuh enO
,elicimod ruoy gnidraug yb yaper ot dnetni I
.denway I ”,gnihtoN“
.dnuorg eht ffo teef wef a naht erom saw ehs erofeb ti deppord dna eutats yvaeh eht no pirg a peek t’ndluoc ehs tub
”?tes eht ni slamina rehto eht erew tahW
.emit a ta wap eno ti koot dna
.debmilc I rehgih eht tnemevom larutan erom a emaceb ti tub
,evom ot dennuts oot
,rood kcab eht ta draug gnipeek saw rettalC
,selsia rehto eht fo eno revo nwod dekool eW
”taR eht ni dnomaiD“   yojne esaelP
em naht ekatpu eht no retsaf saw sabanraB tub ,revo decnalg I
,don a evag rettalC
.emac yeht sa gab eht ni eno hcae deffuts I
.rehtorb sih ta denworf xaM
”,pleh ruoy rof sknahT“
.ekops ti sa swap ym ni detarbiv tI
”,nuf fo tol a saw taht ,sknahT“
.ti dniheb nar taht
.enoemos ot enohp eht no gniklat er’yehT“
.won erots eht fo tnorf eht
”.elicimod wen ruoy tibahni uoy litnu
”,syas yie ,ynihs er’yehT“
.ssenkrad eht ni dnuora debbob thgilhsalf a fo maeb eht neht dna
.evatco na desiar eciov s’nam ehT
,rac reh dekrap dah ynnuS erehw
,tniap eht no stnirp wap kcalb gnivael ruf ytrid ym ,rac strops eht fo
.evird ot em gnihcaet neeb d’ehs nehw
.doow eht ni skram walc gnol gnivael
.sgel kcab rieht tsuj no gniklaw elbuort dah yeht ,em ekil tub
”.yrebbor eht ni sevlesruo gnitacilpmi tuohtiw ti nruter yltcaxe t’nac ew ,dias uoy ekiL“ .deggurhs xaM
…tibbar ,gip ,ekans
.revo ti gninrut ,tar eht ta denworf eH
.sehsub eht otni deraeppasid ehS
snoinapmoc dna ,adnap der eht ,goP ,emit tsaL
”,eutats eht ni yats ot evah t’nod uoY“
,dooG“ .nway a kcab tib I
.flehs yalpsid eht fo edis eht nwod ylwols gnibmilc
,tsalb a neeb dah siht ,eil latot
.tar eht evas ot ylno tuB
.gnihtyreve tsniaga derettalc slliuq reh
”?slamina dnomaid tnaw snooccar dluow yhW“
”?ti tog uoy erehw ksa neve I dluohS“
.srekcus rof saw ssenisub gniklaw sihT
.hgis a htiw deerga xaM ”,rac eht dnA“
.ti fo edisni gniwolb ,naf a ekil
.dne eht yb gnilley saw eh
”,caidoz esenihC eht fo slamina eht ekil sdnuos tahT“
klawedis eht no nrut tniop-eerht a edam I
”,emarf eht no swap ruoy peek ot luferac eB“
.renroc eht dnuora daeh sih gnikop ,dias sabanraB
”,oot gniog teg dluohs eW“
,sah ydaerla eno siht tuB“
.slamina eht elots I ,yakO“
.ffo ti gnikcolb rood latem a dah
”,rettalC ot esoht fo eno evig ot tegrof t’noD“
.dnatsthgin eht no ti gnittup dna
.teprac eht gnola ti gniggard ,ti evom ylerab dluoc I
lworg a htiw pu doots kciredoR
taes s’revird eht otni debmilc I
,ti no denepo lenap a dah ehS
yoj fo maercs a tuo tel I dna denediw seye yM
.gniltsirb slliuq
.od ll’ew tahw s’ereh ,yakO“
.esiugsid a no dah I ,sediseB
.renroc kcab eht ot aera erutinruf eht dnuora su del sabanraB
.tsae gnikool ,dias I
.srehto eht rebmemer ot gniyrt ,desuap I ”…god a
.niaga ffo erew ew neht
.efil ot derrup rac eht dna
.em ta gnitniop ,dias xaM
.tey em knaht t’nod tub ,emoclew er’uoY“
?evlewt fo eno saw siht dias uoy ,xaM“
dooh eht ffo sdrawkcab dils rettalC
.ria eht ni gnirevoh tar etihw a fo mrof eht otni gnicselaoc
.taes regnessap eht ni decalp I taht
.srehto eht naht rewols devom ehs hguoht
”,rac eht evael ot evah ll’uoY“
”.oN“ .em dedrager dna
.rood eht nepo yeht sa noos sa og ot ydaer eB“ .dias stoeD
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ressoR naoR yb
.edisni morf emac ti tuB“
.gnip a saw erehT
,dooh eht otno debmilc rettalC
.dooh eht no toof a gnittup ,denrut ehS ”.huh hA“
.rewot nooccar eht revo gnikconk tsomla
.deksa eh ”?devlovni ynnuS si woh oS“
,edis eht ot devom ehS ”.ynnuS ,uoy knahT“
”.won rof moor ym ni rac eht dna tar eht edih nac eW
”?pleh rof gniksa si tar eht eveileb yllaer uoY“
,draug eht fo weiv fo tuo
.edis eno ot esac ssalg eht tuo ekam ylerab dluoc I dna
,dnuora derettot nooccar mottob ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”,rood kcab eht tuo og ot evah ll’eW“
;deman yltpa saw rettalC
”.emoh gnimoc reh otni nar tsuj eW .ton s’ehS“
.su htiw emac dna gab eht draug ot
,pu detrats ydaerla dah rettalC ,em ot txeN
,eutats eht fo tuo dna pu delriws arua nA
.leehw gnireets eht gnola wap a nar dna
”.siht otni reh gard t’ndid uoy dalg m’I
”…ton ylbaborP“ .delkcuhc ehS
”.ecalp siht no tnirpmi ruoy fo erutan yrotisnart eht leef dluoc I .erawa ma I“
.feiler fo hgis a htiw
,drawkwa saw ti tsrif tA
dekeirhs nam ehT
,dias ti swap ym hguorht dessap eutats tar eht sA
…diap uoY“ .deddon I
.og saw thgir ,pots saw tfeL
.xob eht fo renroc eht morf esor ekoms dna
pu kcab denethgiarts ehs
,eutats siht ni denosirpmi saw I erofeb did ecno I sa
,rewsna ot em rof tiaw t’ndid xaM ”.tnatropmi s’tI“
.edisni erew swap tnorf dna daeh reh dna
”…erus os ton m’I“
.ereh pu tsud eht hguorht dnuora gnilwarc drawkwa gnileef llits ,tsal emac I
.yawa teef wef a resserd eht fo edis eht otni dehsarc dna drawrof detekcor rac eht
.gniliec eht gnola dna pu thgilhsalf eht gnipeews ,dias eciov elam a
”?od uoy did tahW“ .yniarg saw dna
.deddon kciredoR ”?niddalA ekiL“
”,rac eht htiw gnola ,moor s’ynnuS ni s’tI
.kciredoR ,gnorw eb tsum uoY“
.em dniheb thgir revo emac rettalC
.devirra ew emit eht yb dehca sdap
.deb ym otni delgguns dna detrons I
,sthgilteerts eht morf thgil eht fo tsom dekcolb swodniw eht ssorca setarg ehT
.mih htiw saw kciredoR
sdnah sih otni demaercs xaM
?eaf fo dnik emos ebyaM
.thgilteerts eht morf thgil eht ni derettilg ti yaw eht derimda dna
wap yM .htuom ym ni esrup ’senY gnihctulc yllaicepsE
”.deirrow dnuos uoy ,gnorw s’tahW“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
,meht depleh I litnu peels yna teg ton dluow I gnizilaeR
,thgis fo tuo erehwemos nepo dekaerc rood A
.no dloh ot gnilggurts rettalC ees dluoc I dna
.rellortnoc emag a htiw srac emag oediv nevird reve ylno d’I
.tar eht derebmemer neht ,dias I
srepleh eerht reh dlot stoeD
”.etal pu saw I .derit m’I
”.em dnuob taht lleps eht fo seceip eht fo tser eht morf em detarapes yeht nehw
.evisnep noisserpxe sih ,denworf kciredoR ”.eineg a ton
”.noissimrep tuohtiw sgniht ekat uoy nehw s’tI“
.gnihton saw ti ekil pu derepmacs dna
.kciredoR dna xaM ta pu decnalg I
”,emityna ,syob ,emitynA“
deb yffulf ym fo edis eht ffo decnuob tI
.ksat-itlum dluoc I
,sag eht dehsup I nehW
?dennalp sa og tsieh eht lliw tub
!ti evol I …tub
.seye s’tar tsohg eht gniteem dna em dnuora liat ym gnilruc ,deksa I
”?nepo rood eht teg ot gniog ew era woH“
.pmuht teiuq a htiw teprac eht no gnidnal
,erots eht ot yaw rieht no si puorg eht woN
.elddup a ni kcab sih no yal nam eht dna
”.dooh eht no teg ,rettalC
.nettog reve ev’I luah tseB“
elgna hgih a morf nekat neeb dah erutcip ehT
.dnomaid eht revo flesti gnitressa arua sti saw
”,reilrae ereht t’nsaw tahT“
.yaw eht lla esolc t’ndluow dna llufrevo saw gab eht
”.ereh s’tar eht ylno
.eutats gnirettilg eht ot deulg seye sih ,dias kciredoR
,eloh eht rednu weiv otni dellor tI
”,msilobmys lufrewop si caidoZ ehT
”?taht saw kceh eht tahW“
.daeh ym deddon I ”.taht ekil ,haeY“
,rac eht fo tnorf eht revo dekop ttub reH
.em ta dam meht tnaw t’ndid I dna
.emit emas eht ta delley I dna xaM ”!yeH“
.sabanraB dna stoeD dlot I ”!ni teG“
.tar dnomaid eht gnidloh ,kcab saw eh
.slamina fo noitcelloc citcelce na tahw
.ecaf ym revo liat ym tup dna denway I ”.esimorp I“
”!senirugif dnomaid nezod a elots slamina deniart fo hcnub a syas tI“
.erots eht dnuora sdraug eht desahc rettalC sa dnuora yldliw debbob thgil s’namuh rehto ehT
,kcolb eht fo retnec eht ni tas retspmud gib A
.ti deppiznu dna roolf eht no gab eht tes I
.draobdrac fo edam eb ot meht gniwohs
.nwod dereep dna eloh eht dnuora derehtag lla eW
,su retfa derats namow ehT
.slliuq reh tuo deffup dna
”?dna ,nooccar a ,enipucrop A …gnieb maet ehT“
,niaga ladep sag eht gniroolf ,klawedis eht otno tuo denrut I dna
,seitirohtua namuh eht yb no denworf saw enod d’ew tahw taht seivom eht morf wenk I
”,dab si gnilaets wonk I
.llef eh sa yaw eht fo tser eht nepo rood eht gnillup
.innijd fo epyt a er’yeht …ussamaL“
.moor eht fo tuo deklats dna
”.tes elohw eht elots uoy syas swen ehT“
.pot no sabanraB htiw
eutats eht pu gnikcip ,dias xaM
.dias namuh dnoces a
snooccar eht ffo debmilc dna deddon eH
.neercs eht em wohs ot pu em detfil dna ffurcs ym yb em debbarg eH
.ti ta derats dna
”.ereht ti evael t’ndluoc I dna
,derettihc sabanraB
,kcab llef dna depley I
,htab a ekat ot em depleh ehS
.htaerb a tuo welb ynnuS
.yalpsid tseraen eht fo pot eht no dednal dna
taht tbed a uoy ewo I“
”.ti yned t’nod ,uoy s’tahT“
.reilrae revo dekconk d’I taht sllod ypeerc eht htiw flehs eht gnitanimulli
.ni emac yeht sa dias kciredoR
rewot rieht demrof ydaerla dah snooccar eht ,teprac eht no swap ym ot tog I emit eht yB
,nnijd ralucitrap siht fo ytitnedi eht tuo erugif ot hcraeser emos enod ev’I litnU“ .dias kciredoR
,rednow ni rac eht ta derats ehS
.dias sabanraB ”,pu er’uoy ,rettalC“ ”.gninrom eht ni rotanimretxe na llac ot evah ll’eW“
.nrut htooms a edam tsuj rac eht tub ,semag ym ni ekil tfird ot gnitcepxe
,em dna sabanraB neeb tsuj dah ti nehw tsap kaens ot hguone ysae neeb dah draug ksed tnorf ehT
,oN“ ”—ygolopa na htiw rac eht dna slamina dnomaid eht lla nruter ll’eW
.pirg s’xaM tsniaga delggiw I
rac s’ynnuS no seno eht dehctam taht sladep dehcuot swap kcab yM
.uoy sees enoemos erofeb edisni uoy teg s’teL
.dednuos peeb duol A
.saw ti tub ,won gniklat ton s’tI“
roolf eht dehcaer rettalC sa derekcins I tub ,elgna siht morf meht ees t’ndluoc I
,rettalC no delttes dna yaw ruo dnuora kcab gnuws thgil ehT ”?taht saw tahW“
.ffo ti denrut dna rac eht deppots I
nogard eht detfil ehS
,ruf ym morf yalc dna tsud eht lla gnibburcs
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.syad wef a ni gnivom er’eW .ereh emoh ta oot flesruoy ekam t’nod hguohtlA“ .ti dlot I
.reh tcerroc ot rehtob t’ndid I tub ,yob a t’nsaw I
.desiar worbeye eno htiw sabanraB ta decnalg ehS
”.snooccar ot tiforp eht fo tsom evig t’nod“
.peels emos teg yllanif ot denimreted
.deilper rehto eht
.eye eht ni em kool ot nwod gninael
.mih dewollof dna roolf eht no esrup eht tfel yltnatculer I ”.yaw sihT“
.edis rehto eht morf dias namuh a
.tar eht gniucser DNA flesym gniyojne saw I ebyam ,yakO
,erots euqitna eht fo tsieh a dennalp
niaga degnab rood kcab eht yllautnevE
,delley I citnehtua yllaer ti ekam oT
”?siht ekil ,retsoor naem uoy oD ?nekcihC“
”,siht gniyrrac tsaf gnivom eb ot gniog ton er’eW .tihS“
”—adnap der gniklat tep ym saw ti ,em t’nsaw tI .reciffo ,seY“
.swap tnorf reh htiw dleihsdniw eht otno gnidloh
tar eht rof tpecxe ,slamina dnomaid eht lla daolnu reh depleh I sa stoeD dlot I
rac cirtcele elttil eht gnivird em fo erutcip a saw ereht nO
.liat yffulf sih rednu neddih eutats eht dah dna
.god a ekil depahs saw taht erugif pot eht reh dednah I
.ereht tas taht xob latem gib a htiw dnuora gnissem
,gab eht gniyrraC .sabanraB neht
.egnaro gniraes-eye na ni rac strops retaes-owt a dna ,nades kcalb a
.dniheb slamina eht fo hcnub a evael ot evah d’ew naem dluow ti dnA
.sedalb naf deppots eht derevoc taht
,emit siht tuo dekrow sgniht dalg m’I ,goP“
.nwod dewols I oS
,tirips esuoh a neeb d’I nehw em ni devil d’ohw sehctiw eht ot gninetsil morf dlrow larutanrepus eht tuoba tol a wenk I
.sladep railimafnu eht htiw delbmuf I sa ykrej erew spots yM
”.edir teews a s’taht tuB“
,pu kcab delruc I sa em ot txen nwod dehcuorc xaM
,yrenihcam raeh dluoc I
.moc.ressoRnaoR no krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,eson ym gnilknirw em dah ereht kcab llems ehT
.sabanraB dna ,rettalC ,stoeD htiw
.esirnus ot esolc tog ti krad peed taht saw yks ehT
.su woleb teef evif tuoba saw flehs tsesolc eht fo pot ehT
.rehtegot ylteiuq gnikcalc slliuq reh
”.maet eht fo tser eht yap ot dah I tub ,haeY“
.niaga ni kcab emoc ot deirt snamuh eht esac ni
”?yeltneB ynit a gnivird nooccar a taht sI“
.kniht ot deirt dna
,tey pu evig ot ydaer toN
”…ees s’teL“ .dias ehs
.dekrow esiugsid ehT
.rettalC ot txen deppots I sa deksa I
.tar eht ot txen tas dna
.dnah eno htiw eson sih fo egdirb eht degassam kciredoR
.yawa gnilddaw dna gninrut erofeb ,dias ehs
”?meht llet ot gniog I ma kceh eht tahW
.yawa deppord thgil ehT
,skcirb eht tsniaga wap eno tup dna revo deklaw I
.eutats eht ot desu ma I“
.dedda I ”,rac eht dnA“
”?nroh a evah gniht siht seoD
…tuB“ .leehw gnireets eht no swap ym denethgit dna derepmihw I
sepip eht ffo nwod debmilc ehs sa dias stoeD
”?taht raeh uoy diD“
.foor eht fo enil eht revo gniraeppasid
.leehw gnireets noom-flah eht no swap ym tup dna
.taes regnessap eht dnuora roolf eht no meht tup ew os ,ekaf eb ot tuo denrut knurt ehT
,nepo gnuws rood esac yalpsid eht dna
pot hsem eriw eht yawa gnileep ydaerla erew srepleh eerht reH
yella eht fo dne eht dehcaer eW
.rac yot egnaro thgirb a ni yb gnivird em eciton dluow draug evitnettani tsom eht neve tub
.egde eht ffo ,esroh dnomaid a
.tellaw reh morf ssap a htiw denepo ehs hcihw ,ecnartne egarag gnikrap eht ot revo gniwollof
,detciderp dah nooccar eht sA
.yadot reilrae ereht neeb t’ndah esohT
dezilaer won I tahw htiw deremmihs eutats ehT
,ydob eritne sih gnisu tub ,ezis sih flah erew seutats ehT .flehs eht otno
.edis hcae gnola detalumucca dah hsart dna
.tuo tsal dna tsewols eht saw I
.ecaf ym revo liat ym dellup I
ffo demooz ew sa
.emit dnoces a nroh eht desserp I sa
kcol eht sdrawot thgilhsalf deppord s’draug eht gnidloh
,eloh eht hguorht deraeppasid snooccar ruof ehT ”!raelc llA“
”,rebmemer t’nod I“
,meht ta syawedis degrahc dna dessih ehS
.neercs eht no erutcip s’revird eht deppat eH
.rorrim weivraer eht ni decnalg I
.siht ekil eloh eht hguorht pu kcab siht gnitteg erew ew yaw on saw erehT
”.yawa oG“ .kool yraelb a mih evag dna revo dellor I .ekawa em koohs xaM erofeb peels fo sruoh wef a tog ylno I
.srac yot cirtcele dezis-goP fo enil A
,odnoc reh ni kcab tog ew ecnO
.noitcerid s’tar eht ni srae ym dekcoc I ”.seY“
”!esle eno on tub ,ti raeh dluoc goP yhw s’tahT“
.su dniheb pu gnillorts ynnuS ees ot taes s’revird eht ni dnuora detsiwt dna depmuj I ”?goP“
,foor eht fo pil eht revo flesym dellup I emit eht yB
,eno fo renroc eht hguorht eloh a dewehc snooccar ehT ”.kool yeht sa ydruts sa t’nera selit etihw ehT“ .dirg eht otno
.flesym fo dloh a tog I erofeb tnemom a rof taes eht ni yoj htiw nwod dna pu decnuob I
,leehw gnireets eht no deknay I
,renroc eht ni revo saw stoeD
.deksa kciredoR ”?yas ti did tahW“
.foor eht hguorht tuo kcab detixe srepleh nooccar eerht eht
,eloh eht revo dehsalf ti sa kcab dekcud eW
.ti yb derehtob demees esle eno on hguoht
.rehtils gnitaludnu na ni desop ,ekans eht
kcilc duol a saw erehT
”?ereht ni rac a ereht sI
tsehc ym tuo deffup I ”.sknahT“
.tuoyal eht fo pam edurc ym no desab su nettog dah stoeD esolc woh em desserpmi llits ti tub
,sepip dna seriw fo ssem eht hguorht nwod debmilc ew sA
.yella eht otni tuo demooz eW
.yb krow ot thgil mih evig ot
roodkcab eht ot ffo deraor I sa taes ym fo kcab eht otno gnidloh
,ypmub saw ereh tnemevap ehT
.pal sih no potpal s’ynnuS tes dna em ot txen nwod tas tub
.snamuh eht fo yna pu ekaw ot pu sabanraB dnes ot tnaw t’ndid I
.spil sih desrup kciredoR
,pu dedaol saw ti ecnO
,liat sih rednu tar dnomaid a gnidih si sabanraB dna ,gninrom eht ni ytriht ruof s’ti taht neviG“
eloh eht morf depmuj ehS
.efil ym fo emit eht gnivah llits saw I tub
tnemeticxe htiw niaga gnipoohw
.ti nmaddoG“ .derettum xaM
dessorc-ssirc srettuhs latem derrab