gnimoc em was ynnuS
.gnihctiwt eson dna liat
.oot ,srebmilc larutan era senipucroP“
,rotavele eht ffo kcuns eW
.nalp ym ni raf taht nettog t’ndah I .deggurhs I
.worbeye desiar a htiw em ta nwod decnalg eH
.sgniht elbakaerb erom erew rehgih dna
.daeh sih gnikahs ,yawa denrut eh nehT
.yraropmet saw ti sa gnol sa
,pu dnah a dleh xaM
.lautum saw gnileef eht tub ,hcum em dekil eh kniht t’nod I
.detaeper senY ”?taR“
.moc.ressoRnaoR
.erofeb enola tuo neeb reven d’I
.thgieh daeh s’xaM ta
,repsihw a ot esolc ,dengiser erom saw tI
.rekram sti sa desu d’I taht giwt eht no wap a tup I
em dehcaer tsrif ehT
”,goP ,tar eht gnitteg ton er’eW“ .deliaw I
.sessalg reh dniheb htrim htiw gnilkraps seye reh
.yawa gniklaw nageb xaM
.sevael eht neewteb morf su ta nwod deknilb seye wolley fo snezoD
sredluohs s’xaM otno debmilc I
”?yako ,pleh emos rof ksa ,emit txeN“
,pets-dim desuap I
:ti ni sgniht fo yteirav a dah deretne I elsia ehT .nrael d’yehT
.ecaf sih no lwocs peed a dah eH
mra tfel sih ot thgiew ym detfihs dna dehgis eH
.erom delwocs kciredoR tpecxe—
.eciov evitatirohtua s’kciredoR gnitatimi ,swap ym deppalc I ”.neht si ti fooR“ .liat reh gnikcilf ,dias stoeD ”.si
nwod emac sgnaf reH
”.ti droffa t’ndluoc eh dias xaM
.evlewt fo tes lluf a sa meht lles ylno lliw renwo eht ekil skool ,hO .era ew ereH“
.ffo derepmacs sabanraB ”.meht teg og I elihw ereh yats uoy
:gnitseretni gnihtemos dettops d’I tub
,pu hgih siht saw I taht woN
,meht sa ezis emas eht saw I taht won tub
.ffo reh gnittuc ,nehctik eht morf dellac xaM
?tsoc hcuoc eht hcum woh derac ohW
.esool teg ot gniyrt ,delialf dna detsiwt I ”!pleh ,xaM“
.erots eht morf yawa gniklaw
neht dna em ot txen teksab lluf eht tes xaM
ni em derevoc yllatnedicca dah xaM taht ffulf wollamhsram ykcits eht naht tuo teg ot reisae eb ot dah siht dnA
,peelsa lla erew yeht erus saw I ecnO
”?adnap der gnikaerf a taht sI“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ressoR naoR yb
,em dnuora smra mrif owt tpek xaM tub
!pleH ?em draeh uoY“
.su dniheb pu gnimoc ,dias kciredoR
.snooccar eht rof net sevael taht ,thgirlA“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.sruoh wef a nihtiw ffo meht eracs ot elba neeb syawla d’I
.tnaem eh tahw dnatsrednu dluoc I tub
.em ta gnitniop ,dias stoeD
”.ereh hsarc lla uoy gnittel yb ytirahc ylraey ym enod ydaerla ev’I“
!dnomaid fo tuo edam er’yeht tub
.eciov eht tuoba uoy eveileb I .gnihtoN“
,yako saw ti sseug I tub ,sroloc thgirb ym dekil rehtar I
.roolf eht no tlenk dna hgis a htiw dias eh ”…goP“
,deye-ediw eht reh evag I
.denruter sabanraB nehw deksa I ”?taht si kceh eht tahW“
”.pleh t’now snamuh eht wonk ydaerla uoY .drusba eb t’noD“
”,siht htiW“ .deksa I ”?woH“
,flesym esopmoc ot tnemom a koot I
”.esiugsid a deen ll’uoY
.riah sih no deggut I
.elbidua ylerab saw yrc tniaf ehT ”.em pleH“
”.pleh rof deksa tsuj s’ohw s’tahT“ .dias I
.kcuts ,delttar ti tuB
.sdaeh citsalp rieht no selims ypeerc egral
.niaga pleh rof ksa ot eciov eht rof detiaw dna level eye ym ta won
.em sdrawot denrut dna seye sih dellor xaM ”.egatniv er’yehT
,naidraug esuoh a saw I nehw morf ti dezingocer I .kool eht
yaw taht decnalg eH
.hsem rekciw eht fo eerf swalc ym dekrow eh elihw llits dleh I
,sehcneb fo elcric a revo sehcnarb sti daerps eert kao eguh A
ksed tnorf eht ot revo em deirrac eH ”.dekcol s’tI“
.eerf dellup ti sa tsuj renroc eht dnuora emac xaM
.deklaw ti sa ylthgils delttar dna
”?ecirp ruoy s’tahW“
.sllaw kcirb hguorht og dluoc srac gnideeps ehT
”.skcol kcip ot woh em thguat senY“
.hcuoc eht fo edis etisoppo eht no gnittis
.swap ym gnidaerps ,dias I
,goP .enoemos wonk I“
.roolf eht morf dluoc I naht elsia eht fo erom tol a ees dluoc I
,soediv ni seert gnibmilc sadnap der nees d’I
fo tnorf ni doots ew hcuoc eht dniheb weiv ym morf neddih gnihtemos ta detniop neht
.srac ynit fo lluf teksab a
.yliraw rehto hcae deye I dna stoeD ,enog mih htiW
,kcab tog ew nehw noonretfa etal ylno saw ti hguohtlA
.roolf eht revo lla tuo stnetnoc eht gnipmud
.sabanraB ta dekool I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”,gniht erom enO“ ”.og s’teL“
”.meht gnisahcrup ni detseretni er’uoy fi reh llac ot evah ll’uoY .detsil ecirp oN
.rac dlo s’yaK ekil skool eno sihT“
.stoeD neve naht dnuora reggib saw dna
”?ynnuS ekil eripmav a ehs si ,hoO“
hcuoc eht fo edis eht tih I
”.nus eht ni swobniar ekil derettilg yehT“
.em dnuora denethgit mra s’xaM
.ti fo tnorf ni dnats ot revo devom yllufitud eH
”,yenom tsuj s’tI ?laed gib eht s’tahW“
,pu em dekcip eh sA .niaga ,yenoM
,kcils lio na ekil
.knurt eht nwod debmilc
.meht fo deracs era snamuH“
.tar eht evas dna
wollof ot em ta derettihc sabanraB
?gniddik I saw ohW
.rood ssalg eht tsniaga ylthgil ti gnisserp
.railimaf ’senY dna lerriuqs a s’eH
.hgual a htiw derettihc sabanraB ”,niaga rac a evird ot tnaw tsuj uoY“
”.etagitsevni ot emoc yeht fi
”?boj siht si tahw tub
.morf emac yenom erehw
.smra ym dessorc dna deffuh I
.ti nepo ot rood esac eht no llup dluoc eh os
kcab sti morf tuo deffup taht riah gnikool ytniop ,gnol fo noitcelloc eht fo esuaceb saw taht ,esruoc fO
.ti fo dloh teg ot ti dnuora hguone esolc t’ndluoc wap ym tub ,pu ti kcip ot deirt I
tuoba yzah tib a llits saw I
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ffo em gnillup dna
”.cigam yna leef t’nod I“
.striks erow dna ,riah krad ylruc dah ehS .dekil I ,reH
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”?ti pleh ot tnaw uoy t’noD“
.elbarelot tub ,esruoc fo ,esuoh dlo ym sa ecin sa gnihtoN
,pleh dedeen yeht fi tuB
”.naeco eht ssorca ,ereh morf yawa raf yllaer s’tI .anihC morf m’I“
”.thgin ta swodniw dna srood eht revo nwod srab latem gib llup ereh dnuora secalp eht fo tsoM“ .dias stoeD
.em rof derewsna sabanraB ,ecnelis fo stnemom wef a retfA
.kaeps ot deracs oot flesym dnuof I
.ruf drah ,yffup reh htiw rettalC ta dekool lla eW
.nades etihw a dna
.gniht elttil yreve gninimaxe
.flesym ti od ot deirt t’ndah I hguohtla
.ti droffa t’nac ew ,pleh rof gniksa si ti fi neve ,si ti fo trohs dna gnol ehT“ .dias senY ”,goP ,mrahc noitcetorp a fo tniop elohw eht s’tahT“
xaM ot dias I ”,esac ssalg ehT“
.teprac eht no thguac sleehw elttil eht ecnis ,llew yrev llor t’ndid yehT
,deffins kciredoR ”.eno dne-hgih A“
”,krow annog toN“ .deksa I
,ylwols sabanraB dewollof I
.tnatropmi saw noissim siht tuB
.tar a fo erugif dnomaid a laets su pleh ot tnaw dluow snooccar yhw erus ton ,desuap I ”…erocs ehT
,dias xaM ”,gnimoC“
,detaeper I ”,derob m’I“
”.pleh sdeen tI .tar eht teg ,xaM“
.derettihc sabanraB ”,stoeD ,tem lleW“
.gniht namuh a ylno saw gnikahs ebyaM
,enog dah snamuh ym retfa ,tirips esuoh
.ruf ym delffur sdnah reh yaw eht dna noitnetta eht gniyojne
.mih no neeb sah siht drah woh wonk uoY“
.em ta teksab eht detlit xaM ”.thgirlA“
.llams os gnieb detah I semitemoS
.tnemom a koob eht hguorht deppilf eeyolpme ehT
.thgirb oot si ruf ruoY“
.ecnalg gnisiarppa na rettalC dna em evag ehS
daehrevo gnihcaer ,dias xaM ”!wO“
.tnemom a rof esac eht fo tnorf ni doots dna
,tniop ot deen oN
.teksab eht fo egde mottob eht dehcuot ylerab swap tnorf ym
.pal reh otni dezoo I sa yaw eht fo tuo pu potpal eht detfil dna
,won reduol saw eciov ehT ”.em pleH“
.erom dna ,skcor dehsilop ,slamina latsyrc ,seutats ,syot deffuts
.denediw seye siH
gnidliub odnoc s’ynnuS
”?rac a teg ew dluow erehw tuB“ .gnorw t’nsaw eH
.sredluohs s’rehto hcae no gnidnats
.netfo ti od t’ndid I
”.erus rof dettops eb ll’eW
?hcae srallod neT“
.tfihs teksab eht tlef I
.mra ym derewol I
”.struh tI .taht ekil riah ym gnillup pots esaelp tuB“ .liat ym fo ruf eht delffur xaM ”.goP ,oot eM“
.teksab eht ot meht denruter dna swap ym rednu morf srac eht koot dna daeh sih koohs eH
ffo deklats dna denrut eH
,flehs hgih a no er’yehT“
teef ym ta gab ′senY tas I
.xaM ot drow a dehtuom dna
.riah s’xaM no drah deknay I
.su sdrawot spets wef a koot ehs dna
”?em gniddik uoy erA
.dedrawer erew stroffe yM
.em evoba erehwemoS
etarepsed saw ti woN
.retteb ti raeh dluoc I ro
.rehtael eht hctarcs t’nod ,goP ,luferaC“
”.og nac ew os kcab srac eht tup ,goP“
,dehsinif yeht retfA .em derussa stoeD
krap llams a otni yaw eht del sabanraB
.hcaer nac I naht rehgih esac dekcol a ni s’tI ?woh ,tiaW“
”,meht wohS“ .su denioj dna
.rekciw eht ni thguac swalc tnulb ym fo eno ,yawa swap ym llup ot deirt I nehw ,tpecxE
,dias ehs ”,dnomaid s’ti ,latsyrc ton s’tI“ ”?hcum woH
”,foor ehT“ .deksa I
.oot wap taht no walc a hctac ot ylno
.liat ym revo mih ta kool ot hguone delrucnu I ”?tahw ekiL“
.ssertsid sih dnatsrednu t’ndid I ”.kcuF“
.em draeh eh erus ekam ot snier ekil dleh I taht skcol eht no gniggut
?od ot tahw em llet ot eh saw ohW
.nerdlihc ythguan ot evag stnerap kool eht
.xaM ot retnuoc eht ssorca ti dils dna
.suoegartuo yletelpmoc gnihtemos dias tsuj dah xaM ekil gnidnuos
.deb eht rednu lwarc ot moordeb eht ot ffo nar dna sruof lla no pu tog I
.esac eht morf yawa gninrut dna dnah sih gnippord
.enoyreve ekil tsuj ,em was ehs nehw denediw seye s’namow ehT
,mie romuh ot ti yub ot gniog saw I“
,em dniheb dehcterts liat ym htiw sruof lla no wol nwod dehcuorC
”?foor eht morf ni yaw a eb ll’ereht erus uoy erA“
.rorrim eht ni gnicitcarp neeb d’I kool etuc
”,gnivael er’ew dias ew ,xaM“
.em detaerc taht ylimaf eht yb denodnaba ,evael ot elbanU
,ruf gnikcalc ,yffup reh eb ot deraeppa ezis reh fo tsoM
.em ees t’ndid yeht erus ekam ot evah d’I
.dnob railimaf ruo hguorht
.morf emoc dah eciov eht erehw tuo erugif ot gniyrt ,dnuora srae ym deleviws dna ,ria eht ni wap
.edisa gnivom ,deksa xaM
,esrup ′senY koot I ,moor eht tfel ew erofeB .deb fo tuo deotpit I
,tar eht ni detseretni ylno m’I
.yracs kool t’ndid ehs dna
”?og ew dluow esle erehW“
emit rieht gnikat erew snamuh eht dna ffuts namuh dlo tub gnihton htiw dellif saw gnidliub sihT
.noitcelfer ym ta kool ot wodniw tsesolc eht ot revo derednaw I
.roolf eht no em depmud dna ffo em deirp ynnuS ”.oN“
”?gnihtyna leef uoy oD“
xaM ekil tol a dekool eH
.erar erew sadnap der dias eh esuaceb
,neht em detadimitni t’ndah yehT
.enot napdaed a ni deksa ehs
.seuqitna era esehT“
elkcuhc a htiw thguoht I ,etal ooT
”,goP ,gnihtyna dias ydoboN“
.eciov eht draeh I sa eno ssorca devom
?gnihtemos em yub uoy lliW“ ,deksa I
.teksab eht ni kcab meht depmud dna srac pu derehtag eH
”!tar eht pleh ot deen ew ,oN“
”.ti laets dluoc eW“
.mih denioj I sa em no delttes dna sabanraB revo dekcilf seye reH
.ni erew ew erots eht ta smra htob htiw erutseg daorb a edam xaM
”?tnaw uoy ti si tahW“
.dluoc I sa drah sa pu deknay I
.daeh reh koohs stoeD ”.yawyna rettam t’nseod tI“
.elsia dne-daed siht ni enola saw I tpecxE
no krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”.gnihtyna kaerb t’ndid uoy tsael tA“
.serugif dnomaid nezod a sI“
htiw sllod depahs-namuh fo hcnub a ffo gnikconk ,flehs eht tih dna dnuora deppihw liat yM
.dias ehs tahw fo tnetni eht dootsrednu I
”,seinihs eht fo eno si gnipleh rof ecirp ym tuB
.rewsna lausu eht gnivig ,dias xaM ”,hsulp a s’tI“
,sdrow yllaer t’nerew sdnuos siH
1 traP ,ressoR naoR yb
?meht raeh uoy t’ndiD“
smra sih gnissorc ,dias kciredoR
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     .seitiraR dna
,deb ot tnew xaM retfa gnineve eno
”.fo thguoht I eno tsrif eht erew uoy dna ,gniod sdeen taht boj a evah eW“
.swap tnorf ym gnixelf ,dias I ”,bmilc nac I“
.erom neve senY dekil I woN
.em ta derettihc dna pu delwarc sabanraB
.taht devol snamuH
,noisserpxe deniap a htiw og mih dehctaw xaM
.decamirg dna was xaM
.yenom rieht dna snamuH .dias xaM
”!pleh rof gniksa saw tI“ ”.ton yletulosba
,em rof dehcaer xaM sa dias ehs ”,eniF“
.ereht revo esac ssalg eht ni tar latsyrc eht ,yawynA .teppuP“
”,taht ekil mih ekop t’nod ,senY“
.htuom ym ni ti yrrac dluoc I hguone llams saw tI
.reh dniheb gnikcilf ylizal
.wap a tuo kcuts dna tnemom a retfa dias I ”,goP s’eman yM“
,nwod dereknuh eW .dias I
”?ylimaf elbmuh ym dna em ees ot uoy sgnirb tahW“
.dias ehs ”,em tuoba yrrow t’noD
,dluoc I sa hgih sa pu gnihctertS
,nooccar evissam A
,delkraps seye reH ”?sdnomaiD“
.gnivom mih teg ot niaga sgel ym dekcik dna
ekawa ydaerla saw ynnuS
,ygnirps dna tfos gnihtemos no
.swap ym ot delbmarcs I sa em ta eson sih nwod gnikool dna
,dnah eno htiw hgual a delfits senY
,ytpme dna denodnaba em gnivael
eert eht nwod derepmacs meht fo eerhT
”,yaw taht ni teg t’nac ew oS“
.won nooccar a ekil dekool tsomla I
”taR eht ni dnomaiD“   yojne esaelP
smra sih ni dnuora delggiw I
,kcab dereggats I
.dias stoeD ”.em rof skroW“
”taR eht ni dnomaiD“
.htnom siht reilrae mrof lacisyhp a htiw pu nekow d’I nehw denrael d’I gniht tsrif ehT
.dnuora srac eht dehsup I elihw sllod eht pu denaelc
,ni ti debbur nooccar eht sa kool ot dnuora daeh ym gninarc ,dias I ”?tsuD“
.stoeD ot denrut I
,teerts eht dessorc yeht dna ,degnahc thgil ehT
,ereh kcab morf ecaf sih ees t’ndluoc I .dias xaM
llab a ni pu delruc I
”.seinihs eht teg reven ll’ew dna
”.yenom naht rehto syaw era erehT“
,siht ekil ecnalab ot drah saw tI
”,oot meht pleh ot tnaw I
.lla retfa ,tnuom ytsurt ym saw xaM
”?nepo ti teg ot gniog ew era woH
,edis eht ni kcuts llits swalc ym
,ti kcits-nu ot rehto eht htiw wap kcuts eht ta tab ot deirt I
.drow rehtona tuohtiw
,dnuora klaw nac uoY“
.em yb eniF“ .dias ehs
.roop drow eht ta gnikcarc eciov sih ,dias kciredoR
,pohs eht ni namuh rehtona saw ti fI
”.gnippohs yrecorg og I emit txen eno uoy teg ll’I“ ,dias xaM
.dneirf sih ot gnitniop ,derettahc sabanraB ”,rettalC si sihT“
.em deveileb eno oN
.ffo derepmacs dna
,riah s’xaM otni derettum I
.sdeb rewolf dna ,ssarg
.kciredoR deredluohs-pmuls a htiw renroc eht dnuora emac senY ”.gnivael er’ew ,xaM“
.nwod daeh sih dekrej dna depley xaM
”?neht ,ni teg ew od woH“
.sdrow sih ni tbuod eht tlef I tub
.pleh rof gnilley t’nsaw eciov ehT ”.em pleH“
”!sey yas uoy erofeb si ti tahw mie ksA“
.won thgir htiw gnihsarc erew ew eripmav eht saw ynnuS # ”.eniF“
.deppart eb ot ekil saw ti tahw wenk I
.deddon I ”?ynihs yeht erA“
”?elbatpecca taht sI
,ruf ym morf tsud gnikahs ,deb eht rednu morf tuo delwarc I ”.ti od s’teL“
”!lliw I ebyaM“ ”.ees ll’uoy nehT“
,em gnilaets ro ,ooz eht morf depacse d’I gnikniht elpoep tuoba deirrow neeb dah xaM
snooccar eht ta derutseg dna pu tas stoeD
,tnemom a ereht doots I
”?thgir ,srab eht nwod ekat dluow tahT
”.slamina dnomaid evlewt fo tes elohw eht yub ot evah uoY“
.rehtorb redlo s’xaM saw kciredoR
.ereh erew ew yhw no gnisucof
,ezis ni sabanraB defrawd lerriuqs eht ot txen gniklaw lamina ehT
,tar eht deveirter ew ecnO
.denepeed lwocs s’kciredoR
.detsil ecirp a neve ton s’ereht evisnepxe os dnA
.revo reh gnikool ,deksa I ”?woH“
”,derob m’I“  2 fo
”.edisni teg ew retfa ti ot pu teg ot yaw a deen ll’ew os
,sdrow fo kcal eht etipsed ,sabanraB ekiL
,sdnah sih dekcolb ehS
.retnuoc eht rednu morf tuo koob a tog dna
”.pleh rof gniksa s’tI“
.semit lareves ni evom ot deirt dah snooccar
.wodniw tnorf eht hguorht ni gnimoc thgilnus eht ni delkraps senirugif ehT
.derettups dna dekohc ynnuS
serutaef prahs ,seye krad
”.si ti hcum woh ees em teL“
tuo meht ekat ot enoemos deen ll’eW
liat deppirts kcalb dna yarg reh
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.erots eht wonk I“
,redrah delggurts I
.eeyolpme eht fo noitnetta eht teg ot retnuoc eht no deppar dna
,tsehc sih ot dehctulc smra ,em ot txen tas sabanraB ”.hcaer
.kcab dna daeh ym gnittep erofeb edisa potpal reh tes ynnuS ”.yggoP ,oot uoy ees ot eciN“
.gninaem rieht tsol d’yeht taht netfo os sdrow eht detaeper dah rekaeps eht ekil
”…rettalC rof eno ,em rof enO
.tnemom a naht sseL
kcab ym no gnidnal ,swap revo daeh delbmut I
.nottub llac eht tih ot ti fo ffo gnipael dna
”,wen dnarb rallod a ylno er’yehT“
.slamina rehto eht dna ,miH
.sabanraB ta kcab dekool dna desuap neht tub
.teef reh gnilffuhs ,dias ehs ”,prahs yllaer era slliuq yM“
”,yrrow t’nod ,tuo hsaw ll’tI .yalC“
.smra sih otni em delttes xaM sa su neewteb htrof dna kcab gnikool ,deksa kciredoR
reh htiw potpal s’ynnuS no stcaf adnap der pu dekool d’I
,tib a yb em naht rellat dna regnol erew yehT
retsiger eht ot txen redloh a fo tuo drac a dellup eeyolpme ehT
”.sdraug yna tuo ekat pleh dna gnola emoc ot deerga s’ehS“
.lla s’taht ,noisivelet hcum oot sehctaw adnap ehT .oN“
,oN“ .delworg ehs ”!tahW“
.prahs dna gnitaluclac ,em ot revo tuc seye reH
eh dna ,denediw seye s’kciredoR .dias xaM
.renroc eht no senY dna kciredoR denioj ew sa dias xaM
”.eef ruoy sa tser eht ekat nac uoy
”?kciredoR ,ot su ekat uoy did erots euqitna fo dnik kceh eht tahW
.dekcol si esac eht tpecxE“ .dias I ”,tcefreP“
.no dednal d’I afos eht fo kcab eht otno pu gnibmilc
,rewot a demrof snooccar eerht ehT .dias stoeD
.tnemevap eht tih swap ym sa llirht elttil a tlef I
,setunim wef a retfA
.teksab eht fo edis eht ta decnalg xaM
,em ot txen thgir saw ti ekil
.ecalp otni kcab teksab eht dils eh sa delbmurg eh
yhtapme htiw dexim
.gninediw seye reh
”.ereh si slamina ynihs eht htiw esac ehT“
.sehsub eht fo tuo demraws snooccar fo hcnub A .dias stoeD
.elprup s’ti tpecxE
.eliforp wol a edam I
elbitrevnoc elprup a no swap ym tpek I
,sruoh ssenisub retfa ytpme erew taht stnaruatser dna seciffo gnieb tser eht htiw
.pohs ytpme eht dnuora decnalg xaM
,su dniheb desolc rood eht sA
,derettum xaM ,htaerb sih rednU
.tsermra eht revo dna pu debmilc dna
.enog saw enot detaefed ,suonotonom ehT ”!pleH
tliug sih tlef I dna
.lewot hsid a no sdnah sih gnipiw moor eht otni gnimoc ,dias xaM
,yas xaM draeh I flehs eht fo edis rehto eht morF
.tnemom a rof siht deredisnoc I
.teef reh ta em tes dna stipmra ym yb pu em dekcip senY ”.ti
a neeb d’I nehW .nooccar eht dedrager dna
”.sffo tsac s’elpoep rehto gniyub ot poots ton lliw I“ .depsag ylbidua
?ew dluoc rO .delbmurg I
,retsiger hsac eht gninnam eeyolpme enol a rof tpecxe ereh seno ylno eht erew eW
”?oot ,rood tnorf eht no eno eht teg uoy naC“
.tsehc reh ot pu delgguns dna pirg reh morf delggiw I
,em romuh ot dedeen eh tlef xaM taht detlusni tlef I
.sesroh ot did noisivelet eht no sretcarahc eht ekil sredluohs sih otni swap kcab ym dekcik I
.liat sih fo ruf eht morf eriw fo stsiwt owt dellup dna ,dias sabanraB ”,trap taht tog ev’I“
.nihc sih otni daeh ym fo pot eht desserp dna
”?ynnuS ksa uoy t’nod yhW
”,lacigam leef t’nseod ti tub ,gniklat s’ti syas goP“
.em pleh ot xaM teg og ot evah d’I ,gnaD
.sevael dna sgiwt gnisu erots euqitna eht fo tuoyal eht tuo dehcteks I dna
.reh ot derepsihw xaM
”.srac cirtcele yot eht ees t’ndid goP gniht dooG“
.kcab ym revo lla gniyrrac erew yeht tahw depmud dna
syawla tsomla erehT“ .deksa I
,ereht serugif lareves fo eno morf emoc evah dluoc eciov ehT ”.em pleH“
,flehs eht revo derettot I
.pu ti kcip t’ndid xaM
.ehtaerb ylerab dluoc I drah os tsehc sih ot em dennip xaM .delggurts I
?ti hguorht rac a dehsarc I fi tahW“
.stsif rieht ni dehcnelc gnihtemos dah hcaE
.eson sih pu gnilknirw
,ybbol eht ni draug gnizoons eht tsap
.tfel dna denrut xaM ”.sknahT“
,roloc fo neehs a tub
htuom sih tes kciredoR .xaM ekilnu
.tnatropmi saw gnihtaerB
,ereh s’enoyreve taht woN“
.dnuora denrut dna em deromuh eH
.raelc erew sklawedis eht os
.won saw I tahw tuoba suoiruc neeb d’I esuaceb
.yarg yddum a ruf ytterp ym gninrut
.thgin eht otni tuo dna
.reh htiw ssem ot tsuj ,devaw I
.der denrut seye reh dna
,won reduol saw yrc ehT ”.em pleH“
.sevlehs rehgih eht no saw tahw ees ot elgna retteb a em evag siht tub
,erutinruf yna niatnoc t’ndid ti esuaceb yb ti dessap dah snamuh ehT
.srac eht dleh taht teksab rekciw eht rof dekool I sa dnuora daeh ym gnileviws ,elsia eht nwod yltnelis deddap I sa
.thgin eht rof deb ot enog lla dah snamuh eht litnu detiaw eW
.xaM teg og dluohs I
.mih dniheb kram noitseuq a otni delruc saw liat yffulf gib siH
,derettalf m’I ?hO“
.ees ot em detnaw t’ndah eh taht srac eht dnuof d’I taht yrgna dnuos t’ndid eH
kcar taoc eht gnibmilc yb rotavele eht denommus sabanraB
.em gniveileb naht rehtar
”.secnartne pu hgih tuoba tegrof yllausu yeht os ,bmilc t’nac snamuH“ .dias stoeD
”.keew txen latner ruo otni evom nac ew litnu sselemoh yllacinhcet era eW“ .dias senY ”,su eb dluow hcihW“
”!ti tuohtiw tfel uoy ,xaM“
.dootsrednu I wohs ot liat ym dekrej I tub
.ediced meht tel dna tsenoh eb ot dediced I
”,tar eht fo eutats latsyrc eht ,erehT“
,noitcerid yreve morf gninnur emoc lliw snamuh eht ,taht od uoy fI“
niur uoy fi segamad yap ot droffa t’nac eW
.tsehc sih ot em gninnip
.revo llef dna
,elsia txen eht otni renroc eht dednuor I erofeB .ffo deddap I
.ti ekat ot evom t’ndid tub wap ym ta dekool ehS ”.stoeD“
.reh dah tsomla I ,xaM ,ti nmaD
”.morf emac erutinruf eht erehw wonk ot evah t’nseod doR
.nwotnwod fo htuos sesir-hgih wen eht fo eno ni odnoc esuohtneP roolf-pot a denwo ehS
.demaelg seye siH
.daeh sih fo kcab eht ta deralg I .dias kciredoR
.krad dna teiuq saw odnoc eht deb ni snamuh eht htiw os ,nwod tnew nus eht retfa bulc eht ot tuo enog dah ynnuS
”.elsia eht otni kcab oG
.slamina latsyrc htiw dellif renroc eht ni esac a morf emac dnuos ehT
.oot denediw seye sih dna
,hteet ym ni dehcnelc eldnah gab eht htiw dnopser t’ndluoc I
.noituac sih dnatsrednu ot yot hsulp citsilaer a tsuj saw I thguoht yeht nehw roivaheb ddo s’elpoep fo hguone nees d’I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,dias kciredoR ”,boj a teG“
.erots eht fo tnorf eht raen esac yalpsid eht gnikram fael eht dehcuot I
.riah sih fo dloh koot dna
.llat os lla erew snamuh ecnis ,esnes edam tahT
”taR eht ni dnomaiD“
?ecnereffid eht saw tahW .dnomaid ,latsyrC
.dnuora denrut dna deppots xaM ”?goP ,ohw pleH“
.syaw ralucatceps ni hsarc ot deirt uoy ,eno ni dna
.ereht eutats tar ylno eht saw ti
.sdraug evah yeht tuB
.meht pleh ot gnihtyna od dluow I
.koob a ni kcuts eson reh
”,enipucrop a m’I“
.ecnalab ym peek ot gnipleh ,em dniheb gniyaws liat gnol ym
”.pleh rof gniksa si tar latsyrc tahT .did yeht ,seY“
scileR rof ffo tes werc yeltom ruO .oga skeew wef a
.stac rof ekil ,skcapkcab elbbub esoht fo eno mie teg dluoc ew ebyaM“ ,dias senY
”.gnihtyna kaerb ot ton yrt tub
.mih tuohtiw serots tfirht eht pu tih og nac I dna uoy worromot neht ,ruoh rehtona rof ereh mih romuh ll’eW
”,ffo gnifoog potS“
.rehtegot swap tnorf reh debbur ehS ”.ni er’ew ,hoO“
.ecaf ruoy dna kcab ruoy no egnaro eht ,taht toN“
.derettihc sabanraB
daeh ym ffo decnuob srac yoT
.sreh naht regnol saw liat ym hguoht
liat depirts gnol ym delruc I
.srae ym denettalf I
uoy oD .tsieh a gninnalp si ereh dneirf yM“
.eciov eht ni hsiugna eht draeh t’ndah yeht tuB
”,erots tfirht eht ta deppohs evah dluohs ew uoy dlot I“ .hctiw a saw ehS
”.esac eht ni tar latsyrc ehT“ .tnegru erom dna
.stnerap rieht ot od nerdlihc namuh ekil ,tuo drow eht werd I ”?esaeeeeelP“
.skcor htob erew yehT
.ssalg eht no deppat dna dnuora pu
.dnuos eht sdrawot detovip srae ralugnairt yM
”?erocs eht s’tahW .sdnepeD“ ”?ni tnaw
.xaM sa llat sa tsomla erew yeht ,yaw taht dekcatS
.hcuoc eht no tas ehs sa potpal reh no gniyalp dna
”,nalp a htiw pu emoc s’tel
”.reh ot klat og ot krad retfa litnu tiaw ot evah ll’ew tub ,pleh deen ll’eW“
.derettihc sabanraB ”,tniop a sah ehS“
.liat ym ni eson ym deirub dna
,toob ot derebmuntuo ylhguoroht erew ew dna
”?tar tahW“ ”.dekover era segelivirp redluohs ruoY“
,muinomadnaP deR fo rohtua ,ressoR naoR yb
,dedneffo dekool sabanraB
.gab eht ni kcab ti yrrac dluoc I
,sgel kcab reh no mih fo tnorf ni gnittis ,dias ehs ”!gnilrad ,sabanraB“
”,taht tsuj toN“ ”.tar dnomaid A“
.mih ta eugnot ym tuo kcuts I
,em htiw teksab ytpme eht gniggard
”?tnereffid yna siht si woh ,eduD“
,ynnuS htiw semag gnicar rac fo sruoh deyalp d’I
”.rehtie ,mrahc noitcetorp lacigam ’senY leef t’ndluoc uoy dias uoY
?em eveileb uoy t’nod yhW“
.dias I ”,eno siht tnaw I
”.rood tnorf eht s’erehT“
erew taht sevlehs eht dennacs I
.sehcnarb eht morf su gnihctaw
,swodahs eht ni sgnidliub eht ot esolc gnikcits yB
.sgnidliub eciffo owt neewteb tas taht
,syot erew sevlehs mottob eht fo tsoM
,nwot eht fo trap siht ni seno laitnediser wef eht fo eno saw
.dias ehs ”,nooccar a rof deroloc ylthgirb yllaer er’uoY“
.reh yfsitas ot demees tahT
.dias xaM ”,sredluohs ym evas pleh dluow tahT“ ”.rellorts a rO
.roolf eht revo lla derettacs dna
.seitiraR dna scileR dellac revir eht raen erots euqitna na s’erehT“
”,serots tfirht ta pohs elpoep roop ylnO“
,nees reve d’I tsegral eht
.eciov wol a ni dias ehs
senirugif eht laets s’retcarahc eht woh tuo dnif ot
.ruf hcamots kcalb ym ta nwod dekool I
,riah nworb trohs—
”.evael ew erofeb nosrep taht pleh dluohs ew ,xaM“
,gniniart cigam lautca dah kciredoR
.sgel kcab ym otno pu doots I
.nageb ynnuS ”—oc fO“
.eciov eht tuoba lla togrof dna ti ni srac eht dah taht teksab rekciw eht fo edis eht dettops I
.kcen reh dnuora swap ym werht dna sgel reh no doots I ”!ynnuS ,ynnuS“
,rotavele eht fo tuo dednuob I
.esoht fo rehtie ni em gnittup yeht erew yaw oN ”.riah ym dnA“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.srac rieht ni yb gnissap snamuh wef eht yb decitonnu deyats I
.mih dewollof xaM fi ees ot gnitiaw tuohtiw yawa deklaw kciredoR ”.og s’teL
.htaerb ym gnisol yliratnemom
.weiv ni srehctaw eht peek ot kcab daeh ym gninarc
.reh hcaer ot tnemeticxe ym ni elit eht no elttil a gnilbbarcs
”.srac ynit eht ees ot detnaw I“
em evag dna htgnel s’mra ot tuo em dehsup ynnuS
emit txen ni enuT