.no kcab gol tsuj ot em rof ysae oot eb dluow tI
”.uoy tsuj er’uoy woN
,meht htaeneb nwod gnilruc lirdnet a htiw
.nwot otni rehtruf gnirolpxe detrats ev’I
,thgiew fo esnes a edivorp sraluger eht ,lla ti fo tsdim eht nI
”.knup a fo deen eros ni eb tsum nwot sihT
.em nihtiw skcilc
.tsehc ym revo nwod dna dnomaid eulb eht gnola sessiK
.egarag eht nepo ot nottub eht tih dna rac eht ni bmilc I .og ew ereH
.esion fo kcal eht morf daeh pu-deffuts ym ni gnizzub srae ym ,ecnelis evitaler ni su sevael ffo gninrut rac ehT
,stol gnikrap dnuora gnilcyc srac sgnirb evaw hcaE
,sehctac yllanif emalf ehT
tahW“ ”.lla ta toN .oN“
.tnemevom gnilarips fo ecnad citoahc a s’ereht dna
,sseug I ,noisulces ni nwot eht dnuora gnivil sklof era erehT
,detcepxe ev’dluow I naht reteews raf si etsat ehT
gnol a ni tsrif ehT
.esiwrehto ”ystra“ tsuj ro
.ffo sttim eht ekahs nac eh os elbat leets eht no nwod tes ylkciuq steg sihT
,aroruA dna ;tsiaw reh dnuora dehcnub triks
.stnerap nwod gnihgiew smurtnat ,sliat depmirc ,seidob fo snoisilloc llams
”,yhw wonk t’nod tsuj I dnA“
.sub eht no evif-ytnewt tuoba dna ,thgiN yrratS ot s’madA morf klaw etunim evif-ytrof a tuoba s’tI
.srekrowoc gniddehs morf ereht dna ereh deggans stib elttiL
,)ti pleh nac I sa hcum ,em rof ten erom on—esruoc fo ,rac eht ni kcab saw enohp llec(
.tsetorp fo egniwt a evig skeehc ym revo sracs dnarb-ezeerf eht tub
.mur sih ta spis eh sa ssalg sih fo mir eht revo em ta skool eH
nrut ni yppah os em sekam taht yhW
eciffo eht dniheb oitap eht ot revo em detivni s’eh dna ,oiduts elttil taht ni gniyats htnom dnoces ym otni os ro keew A .saw eh
.ffuts hcamots tsuJ“
.taes s’revird eht dniheb tsuj
”.heh“ fo tros a eganam od I tub ,tey hgual etiuq t’nac I .yas I
.meht hcated ot gniyrt fo wohs a
.gnol yats reven yeht tub
,tsrif hcnul eht stae ehS
.I naht rellat sehcni wef tnacs a gnidnats
.flesym rof pu tliub d’I efil eht eltnamsid ot nigeb I ,enod si esuoh eht fo tnuocca ym ecnO
,tuo sllor edit neht dnA
.skoob eht fo pot no dessot dna skooh rieht morf devomer era sgnitniaP
.esnecil s’revird dlo ym yortsed ot yrt I sa gnitalitnevrepyh
erom ecno em dnuora smra reh nettog s’ehS
.kcen ym fo edis eht no nwod sesserp ,srehto eht naht yldnips erom ,driht A
.skoob eht nur pleh dna sexat eht od em gnivah s’eH
.tnelis llaf I taht tA
.won ti rof lufknaht m’I dna ,elihw a ereh gniyats saw I raelc saw ti ecno erom thguob d’I
,gnimehcs dna gninnalp ym lla no
,hgual I ”.ebyam ,sevreN
.ruf ym ni slarips gnicart eson etoyoc tfoS
.ecalp ni liof eht sdloh wap A
”?rebmemer uoy did em tuoba tahW“
.od ot evah ll’tI
.senots dehsilop-evaw eht era eW
,wap reh no keehc reh detser ehs yaw ehT
,pu nethgiarts dna pat eht morf puc ym llifer I
.em dnuora ni esolc ot smees
rab eht dniheb roolf eht morf niats a pu dekcip sah triks ym dna ,sraet ym morf pmad llits s’trihs yM
.retfa noos tuo meht werht I
.gnihgual aroruA tog ti ,taht dnoyeb dna
.tsaoc eht ot kcab yaw rieht no hguorht kcab gnidaeh ro
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.hguorht ssap ylno dluow ohw esoht lla rof edivorp ot deen eht hguorht rehtegot sdloh flesti nwot ehT
ni tfel I seno eht—
.ma I ohw em edam
edicius fo mrof a erom saw tI
.pleh reh tel llew sa thgim
.edit hgih txen eht litnu sisats elbatrofmoc a
.ti htaeneb hsac rof gniggid neeb dah enoemos hguoht sa weksa nworht si sserttam ehT
.hgis a htiw riahc kcadnoridA eht otni kcab selttes eH ”.hguoht
.tenretnI eht gnihcuot morf peek ot—gnihtyna—
.tsiaw ym gnilddarts s’ehs litnu em revo pu eno stfihs dna seenk reh otno rehtruf elttil a pu snael ehs ,noitatiseh s’tnemom a retfA
.dessarrabme ylgnicnivnoc s’ti gnipoh ,elims a eganam I
.dnabsuh ym was I
.madA pleh ot tuo kcud I ,gnol erofeb ,dna ,krow ot kcab steg etoyoc eht nehT .yzoc
.eromyna krow ta dedeen ton s’eh nehw gniraeppasid ta doog yllaer s’nafetS     .shgual eH
.tuo denrut era sehtolc dlo gniniatnoc sexoB
.gnihtaol-fles fo ecamirg taht naht rehtar
”.ti fo ffo gnignah flah fo daetsni deb ruoy no elbatrofmoc eb uoy tel osla si od dluoc I tsael ehT“
.elbissop sa elttil sa
.wap reh ni ezeeuqs a hgiht ym gnivig erofeb ni delkcub lla steg dna taes s’revird eht otni selttes etoyoc ehT
,snoitome esoht fo lla sa rab eht fo egde eht ta hctulc I
.yeksihw etihw ym otni eci eht gnirrits ylsuovren yb ecaps taht llif ot yrt I dna ,dnopser ot tib a em sekat tI
.niaga leg ti ekam ot elba neeb reven ev’I dna
”.mmM“ ”.nwod gnidniw s’nosaeS“
,wap ym ni rethgil wolley yttihs eht dna esnecil delgnam ym ot nwod ,dnuora kool I
gnilriws dna gnilcriC .ecaps knalb a gnidnuorrus eb ot mees sthguoht yM
.gnihtyna yas I erofeb pots tub ,tsetorp ot trats dna elkcub ym rof elbmuf I
,deb eht otno pu flesym luah dna hgual I ”,tniop dooG“
.mur fo hcni rehtona htiw gnola raj sih ni eci fo ebuc rehtona ssot ot esuap A ”.oS“
.rethgit elttil a em dnuora mra reh sguh dna waj ym rednu pu elzzum reh skcut aroruA ”.oN“
.wap eht yb em gniggut
”.dnats nac uoy fi eeS
.edis eht ot trihs ym ssot ot deganam ev’I tub ,su neewteb pu dehcnub llits s’triks yM
”.tnaw uoy revenehw tuo daeh ot eerf leef oS“
,puc eht dnuora sregnif ym sediug dna sreh ni swap ym fo eno sekat ehS
,oot ,no gniog gaw a fo tib a tog s’ehS
.boj a teg t’nac I tuB
”.krow dluow siht derugif
detreva-tey-neddus a ta em edisni tfihs elttil a dna wap ym ni hctiwt A
.wohyna regnol hcum ereh eb ll’I enigami t’nod I
,teiuq dna railimaf eciov reh ,tsenrae ni eciwt ro ecno deklat ylno ev’eW
.niaga rab eht dniheb kcab spils dna gab reh ni kcab srepap dna koob reh skcut ehS
.ecnelis ni enim tsniaga daeh reh stser tsuj
,ma I ereh tey dnA
htolcyrret eht hcnelc ,hteet ym tirg I
,cinap otni sodnecserc yteixnA
tsuj s’ereht ,ti tuoba kniht I nehW
,ffo koot I erofeb htnom a rof dekcuf t’ndah eW .ecracs neht dna
.flesreh rohtua eht yb
.nwodtnuoc eht morf eciov sih ezingocer I dna ,snirg lesaew ehT ”?huh ,sgnitS“
,rab eht fo egde eht tsniaga dekrap ttub ym htiw pu dniw I tub ,seirt wef a sekat tI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.dekaos era trihs ym fo eveels eht dna skeehc ym sa ,yltnerappa ,emit elohw eht gnibbos neeb d’I
,éfac eht ni tuo kcaB
.tnetnocsid fo sraey ynam os gniwollof
,don dnoces a dna wollaws yrd a stnarraw tahT
tuo tel dna ,swap ym ni
.tluciffid erom si moor gnivil ehT
.seitnap dnalb fo kcap a barg ot no ylrae
.moor eht fo tser eht ot ees I elihw rood ym yb yltaen tes si VT eht dna ,hguoht ,siht rof dennalp d’I
”.sexat t’nia taht tub ,od I tahw ta doog m’I
,trihs a ,snaej fo riap a gnidloh kcar gniyrd gnidlof a ,rehto eht no dna ,sehtolc ytrid fo elip a si edis eno no ti ot txeN
,railimaf sllems tI
.oot slrig ekil uoy ebyam ,lleH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.wonk t’nod I…tsuj I“
.flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer eb lliw hcihw
,deb eht fo egde eht no leenk ot sevom neht ,ssik kciuq rehtona em evig otni snael ehs ,gninnirg llitS ”.mhmM“ ”.ecin saw tahT“
.snoihsuc nrot esoht htaeneb ,ereht gnihtoN
,nihc ym rednu neht
,rac eht ni ydaerla si deen I ffuts eht llA
.luferac lla s’tI .ton s’tI
.aroruA no pirg ym niatniam ot drawrof gninael sredluohs ym evael I
”?evael uoy d’woH“
.teg nac yeht pleh revetahw rof yppah era éfac eht dna yats-gnol eht htob os ,nosaes ysub eht otni llew er’eW
”?ereh tuo uoy yhW“
.kcab gnitnac srae
.thguoht eht ta hgual I
,swodahs derrulb tsac meht hguorht gninihs sthgil tnecseroulf eht dna ,skcab eht gnola pu kcalb deoottat neeb evah srae siH .em no gnitiaw
.em eciton ot mees neve t’nseoD
,tsrif ettal eht sknird ehS
”?snibac eht fo enO“
,ylisae oot citsalp kcils eht ffo pils dah sdap ym tub ,tcnitsni tsrif ym saw tahT
.tsewhtroN cificaP eht ni reenigne erawtfos dna ,rotide
.em otni hsarc ,meht fo shtnom enin ro thgie
.naom delgrug fo tros a
gnihtemos ton saw
.emarf fo tuo gnirats ,tsif no keehc
.em ta kool nac ehs taht os hguone tsael ta ecarbme eht morf pils smra ruo gnitteL
gniknirhs si ,ssenerawa eritne ym ,dlrow eht fo noitpecrep ym dna ,gnisnet era selcsum yM
.naem I ,erus ,lleW“
.pu tup ot sriahc owt tsuj s’ereht os ,elbat reh saw tfel saw taht lla
.tsael ta ,em rof toN
,em evoba hcuorc reh morf nwod selttes ehS
.edis yreve no ni demmeh tlef llits I tub
gnihtemos…remotsuc a gnihtemos tsuj…tsuJ“
ksir hcum oot lla s’tI
,esicrexe ”gnippohs erofeb sgel eht hcterts“ a neeb tsuj dah ti ,yllanigirO
,doog gnikool erew skeehc ym dias ehS
.taht rof pu edam naht erom dah thginot ,lleW …d’eW
.knis eht fo flah ytrid eht ni sessalg dna setalp fo kcats a s’ereht tub ,naelc depiw s’nehctik ehT
”.tnorf pu uoy egrahc I yhw’S
”.nwod gnidniw s’nosaes diaS“
.shtaerb ruo tsuj fo sdnoces gnol wef a
.nac I sa ylteiuq sa yrc I
”.klaw hguone ytterp a s’ti
.taht od ot naem t’ndiD“
.krow esle enoemos gnihctaw ekil leef seod ti fi neve
.llips a gniksir esnes oN
”.thgiarts mees uoy tuB“ .seillat tI .don I
htiw em ot nwod snirg dna ssik eht morf pu snael ehs ,ereht m’I ecnO
.flah a dna raey a ebyam rof ereh evil nac I dna
”?naem uoy od woH ?waS“
.em dniheb depmirc liat
.dnah ym nihtiw nac I tseb sa esnecil eht gnilpmurc
”.seceip elttil otni meht tuc tsuj
.fo maerd ylno nac I ssenllits A .reh fo trap
.ekatsim eguh a edam evah I
.mur eht nwod retaw eci gnitlem eht gnittel
.oot ,ni gnimoc s’ehs rehtehw tuoba noissucsid oN .ni su teL
thguoht yna tuohtiw saw I tahw nwod erot I
,sdnats tar ehT ”.ydal ,thgirlA“
,niaga rab eht dniheb yaw ym ekam I dna rehto hcae tsap edils eW ”.eb lliw I“
.denrub ecnis gnol dah ,saw-taht-em fo foorp tsal taht ,esnecil ym nevE
,sevael on htiw sehsub ynroht ,ralugna
.knis eht nwod epiw tsuj yltsom I os ,si sa hguone naelc s’ti tub ,moorhtab eht fo ssap kciuq a ekam I
,gniyrc trats ll’I ,htuom ym nepo I fI
.gnikrow t’nsi sihT .revewoh
.skeehc dednarb ylwen htiw lesaew desserd ylippols a naht
,ylyrd srumrum enoemos dna ,yawa detfil si keehc ym tsniaga desserp saw taht ’gnihtemos‘ tahT
,sutcir ylgu na ni nethgit ecaf ym leef I ”.raeh ot tnaw I“
.tigel eb ot deen uoy ,syad eseht sboJ“ ,seunitnoc eH
.nibac eht fo rood eht ot spets fo lufdnah eht klaw ew sa reh no nael I
tub…elbissop sa tseb sa derraJ morf terces a ti gnipeek
.em dniheb si elit gniliec kcalb-dna-ydnugrub ehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
;evird taht no desucof ylesnetni s’eH
.kcawht a elbat eht fo gel eht evig ot liat kciht sih gnisu ,sdnats dna riahc eht fo tuo sedils madA
.ot ton gniyrt tsael ta si ro—
.snway delfits dna sliat fo poord ehT
,ecnelis taht ni llits dloh htob eW
.stnapucco eht no gnikcehc ,dnuora kool I
,ecaf a fo erutseg tcartsba na sa detrats dah tI
.ni worg ot elihw a gnikat erew stops devahs eht llA
.syadiloh rof hguone mraw tey ton tub ,retniw eb ot hguone dloc toN
.dias raeb taht
”—siht retfa nwod esolc amm’I
,wap eno htiw ecalp ni tlebtaes eht gnikcilc ylismulc
drac tiderc deripxe…hu ,ot dedeeN“
.trihs ym fo kcen-poocs eht evoba pu gnikeep—
,daed ylniatrec tsomla s’tI
.delio llew oot ,segnih esool era stnioj yM
.elit gniliec eht no krow ym morf hsurb eht no tfel cilyrca kcalb eht htiw yldi swalc ym tniap I ,ecnelis eht nI .gninnirg
.hcnul rof pu skcip neht ,ruoh na rof spid
.snibac eht drawot setius eht fo kcab eht dnuora gnidaeh
em morf gnihtemos redro ll’ehs syad emos
)emoh sih osla si esoppus I hcihw(
”.yrros m’I .hguoht ,deksa evah dluohs I
”,neht ,efil ruoy tuoba tib a em lleT“ ”.ecno ta tih lla
,thgiN yrratS dniheb sehcnuah ym no dehcuorc
—wonk t’nod I dna railimaf os dna ereht syawla tsuj er’uoY“
.roloc tnereffid a detniap si elit hcae dna gniliec pord a sah thgiN yrratS
,thgiN yrratS ta cinap fo hsurc eht sa dab sa htnet a teg t’nseod dna ,gnol tsal
yas dluoc I sgniht eht lla fo kniht I
detfihs-txetnoc s’ehs sa ,hguoht ,edisni teg I emit eht yb nettogrof ylbativeni evah ll’I
,hguoht ,madA htiw tnemegnarra wen siht htiW
,rab eht otno pu flesmih sekih nafetS
.ti od nac I ebyam tub
?yako ,hguoht ,emoh uoy teg s’teL“
.nwod kcab ti gnihtooms neht ,ruf nat-yarg ni worruf a gniwolp
.riomem aidem-dexim a ,ylla
taht morf dehctiws I dna
.sbos no gnikohc dna ria rof gnipsag
.detcelloc ev’I swollip fo kcats taht otno kcab delttes ev’eW .srumrum aroruA
”?yako ,pu uoy teg s’tel ,no emoC“
,tnecs-wons gniregnil
.ssalg tsniaga eci fo gniknilc tnasaelp eht yojne htob ew dna lriws ym seipoc eH
egarag eht ot kcab yaw eht no VT eht barg I
.ti otni adnik tog I .yrroS“
.ereh tog uoy nehw sreksihw ruoy fo tuo deracs erew uoy tub ,erofeb ekil erew uoy tahw wonk t’nod I
”.ereh tuo denoitisnart dna tsew tuo emac uoy oS“
,selims dna pu skrep ehS
syawla I ,erofeb meht gnitlem fo thguoht reven d’I“
”?erofeb yas uoy d’tahW
.sucof otni kcab seye ym knilb I dna ruf pu-demmug ym morf yawa deirp si liof eht sa rethgual s’erehT ”.kcuF“
.tey thgir etiuq stuc eht evah t’nseod eh syas madA tub
.erutcip rieht ta hgual ro ,noitseuq rieht rewsna dluoc I .kniht d’I
.etihw ni emoc deedni sah dnarb-ezeerf eht dna
.ruf tnrub ,ypsirc ,dettam fo sehctap sa pu wohs srab ehT
.flah ni tuc neeb s’taht guj klim a fo trap rewol eht revo gniggut
.erus ,lleW“ ”?mmh ,yraterces A“
.hctid a otni ti dellor I sa dehsart saw rac ehT
,keehc ym no ruf fo sdnab etihw esoht fo eno gnola gnicart eson reh leef nac I dna
.ereh tuo ti edam I ecnis enoyna—yb dehcuot neeb ro—
.elzzum etoyoc derepat-yleniF
.ffo reh tuc ot hsur dna wap reh ta barg I nehw ,niaga ksa ot nepo htuom ,snrut ehS
.won sraet dekcinap fo egrev eht no m’I tub ,erom gnilims detrats dna ,yltnecer ,hcum sa gniyrc deppots d’I
.saw I ohw regnol on m’I taht rednimer tsal enO
.mihw emos no peek ot dediced I taht ,tnatropmi ro gib gnihton
ebuc eci rehtona pit ot su neewteb elbat eht ssorca snael dna
,edis ym no ot emoc I
.semit erom wef a rethgil eht ta kcilf I
,taht ta hgual eW
”,ot epahs on ni er’uoy tuB“ “—
.ytiunitnoc fo esnes a edivorp ot edit wol dna hgih gnirohcna
.xes ecnis emit gnol a neeb s’ti tub
,eveels a hguorht kcuts llits mra eno rof tub ffo trihs htiw ,em
,keehc hcae no eerhT .senil thgiartS .seY“
doolb fo spord erom wef a tuo dezeeuqs I ,tnemom a rof gnikniht retfA
dna ti fo retteb kniht ot smees neht
,sdon ehS ”.yrev ,haeY“
tub yako yllatot s’tI“ .yrgna ton tub
.tegdub ym fo tuo hcum oot ton s’ti ,eeffoc pird ot kcits I sa gnol sa dnA
.kcab worg ot skeehc ym no ruf eht rof regae erom eht lla em edam nosrep ni ti gniees tub
.cimoc a morf gnihtemos spahrep tub ,citsilaer toN
,tsal eht naht ylidaer erom eno siht nruter I
.don mrif a evig dna riahc ym ni thgiarts pu tis I
.thgiN yrratS ot kcab daeh I semitemos dna ,evif yb pu raelc sgnihT
.wen gnihtemos htiw—
.ti nwo d’I derugif tsuj I ebyaM
.srae ym drawot elzzum ym morf kcab enil htooms A
,gnirraj s’ti ,gnola thguorb yllatnedicca d’I gnihtemos yb detnorfnoc m’I emit hcae taht
.evird tnatropmi-lla sih drawot detcerid s’eh hcihw
.yats-gnol repaehc a dnif I fi ,regnoL
.yhw ylirassecen ton fi neve
etihw sdrawot tuo nwolb erew enecs eht hguoht sa ,sliated ton
.gniytip naht rehtar ,dnik s’elims reH
,em sehctaw aroruA
.od reven I tub ,flah a dna ruoh na tuoba ni ereht sub lanoiger eht ekat dluoc I
,eippih ro retspih s’ti fi ediced t’nac I
.sknird eht rof purys derovalf fo selttob esoht lla gnignarra dna rab eht nwod gninaelc yb trats I
,deticxe tub suovren gnikool
.sdnarb ym fo sepirts eht ot ralucidneprep enil a gnirolpxe eson ,don tniaf A
”?emoh kcab ,yppah uoy ereW“
.lamron ot kcab m’I litnu
,hguoht ,tuo mooz uoy nehW
I litnu uoy ot klat neve t’ndid I dna efil gnikcuf diputs ym ni stnatsnoc ylno eht fo eno tsuj er’uoy ,wonk t’nod I
.skramwalc eht gnola doolb deraems dna edis eht gnola regnif ym tuc ylluferac I ,dedderhs neeb dah staes eht ecnO
,tfos drawot kcab dna yltsirb ot ylbbuts morf og ot shtnom wef a ekat ll’ti esoppus I
”.og ot evif ,nwod enO“
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.htaerb ym dloh I
.pu trihs ym edils reh tel ot hguone kcab ym hcra I ,elbissop sa tseb sa sredluohs reh no swap ym gnipeeK
.llik ot deirt d’I eno eht
.ecnatsni hcus tsrif eht neeb dah stnemragrednU
”.drow a tuohtiw tfel dna ffuts ym dekcap I
.erofeb pots eht ta sub eht ffo tog dna dnaltroP tuoba suoixna oot tog I esuaceb dekcip nwot a
.nrut ni reh gnihctaw em sah syawla thgis eht tuoba gnihtemoS
.flesym etsat dna ,reh llems I
.oga shtnom ruof litnu pu
”,erew uoy ohw fo strap eseht lla dehsart ro ffo denrut uoy oS“
”?neht ,kcab gniog oN“
.noitanalpxe na htiw pu emoc ot gnilggurts
.tfel eb dluow tahw fo
?spahrep ,rehcaet A
.gnihtyna derutcip dah I kniht t’nod I
”?yako si siht dnA“
.ruf ym otni pees ot strats ti dna tniap eht sniht ssalg eht ffo noitasnednoc ehT
,kcalb ni detniap I
.pu dnuorg eht morf gnitrats
.dloc repus srab eht teg annoG“
.ecnelis ni stiaw ylpmis eh erehw------enod dah pohs dom eht ta tar taht gniht eht—
.ralugnatcer naht rehtar seno derepat esu ll’I dnA .kcab rehtruf elttil a eno elddim eht trats annog m’I
”?ereh kcab yako uoy…hu ,yeH“ ”.yeH“ .kaorc I ”—I“
.od ot tuoba m’I tahw fo
.wonk t’nod I…tsuj I ebyaM“
”.ydeeps kool uoy ekam ll’tI
.knird a htob su ruop I
.ssensselepoh elbirroh emos ni pu dniw ton dna seye ym esolc nac I
,hguoc em ekam ot strats ,citsalp gninrub fo gnikeer ,ekoms eht emit eht yB
”.yawa meht gniworht
,nafetS dna em ot nwod er’eW
.kcab lesaew dehcra ,ehtiL
.kcab eht ot taes regnessap eht morf pilc rednib a htiw rehtegot dleh srepap fo faehs a sevom ehs sa tiaw I
,roolf eht ot gnilpmurc m’I neht dna ,yrc delfits a tuo psag I sa snethgit rab eht no pirg yM .won
.ssenillis fo tnih a tsuj
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.gninethgirf neve ro
,em ot txen stis eno oN
,elzzum emas tahT
gnileef no kcab gnidloh fo syad esoht lla ,raef fo etats emos tsael ta ni gnivil fo shtnom esoht llA
”.gnicreip a teg ot thguo uoy dnA
.tuo tniop I nibac eht fo tnorf ni ecaps a otni sllup dna snirg aroruA
,norpa dna triks ym nethgiarts ot hsur I dna ,rood eht ta pat tfos a s’erehT
.roolf eht no dnuora derettacs dna sdaolmra ni ffo dellup era skooB
,skoob ruof fo rohtua eht si ehS
,deb eht otno kcab espalloc I
.tsael ta ,swalc yna gnikaerb tuohtiw ecneirepxe eht fo tuo emoc ot deganam d’I
.em ot txen leenk ot deb eht otno pu sevom ehs ,moor ekam I sa
.srae ym nettalf neht dna ,sdnuos esoht fo tuo gninaem sesrap dnim ym sa pu krep I
.sdeen ti ezis eht eciwt tol gnikrap a sah tekram ehT
.eert a fo aedi nA
dedne ruf nworb eht erehw esnes ot gniyrt
,flesym rof etarebiled eb ot evah I dna ,srobhgien eht rof teiuq eb ot evah I
;pu gnisolc sehsinif ,elihwnaem ,aroruA
trofmoc eht ni daetsni lever dna
.ssalg sih ot nwod gnilkcuhc ,syas madA ”,rewols tub emaS“
.os od ot gnihca traeh ym ,nrot dna
.semit tsrif suovren fo
.mhmM“ ”?klaw ot doog uoY
.ereh dnuor‘ gniht a t’nia xeS
.tnorf ym nwod etihw eht otni epahs dnomaid a gnieyd m’I ,thginoT
.em fo tnorf ni ereh
”.ytpme flesruoy deirc uoY .knirD“
,daetsni tuoba kniht ot gniht doog a s’tahT
,yzarc eb ll’tI
.ecaf eht ot ebuc-eci na em steg taht sa hgual I ”.ssob ,gniht eruS“
.ypeels sdnuos aroruA ”?uoy dnA“
.kcen reh fo epan eht ot nwod tuons reh fo pit eht morf ruf fo kaerts knip thgirb a htiw mussopo yknup a yb deteerg saw I tub ,meht yb tuo dedriew eb d’yeht taht deirrow neeb dah I
.ereht morf strats dna stif ni seunitnoc noitarolpxe ehT
.elims dnik a otni gninetfos nirg reh ,sgurhs aroruA
,seunitnoc eh sa ,esolc gnitteg tub
.elzzum ym ot ssik rehtona sserp ot ni gninael ,syas ehs ”,dooG“
yletulosba dna ,etulosba era yehT
.rac a evah uoy nehw
.tekcop tekcaj reh ni nugtohs gnidir sgabaet eht fo eno dna reh rof retaw toh fo top a dna ,retaw ados a
,tnedifnoc era sekorts-hsurb yM  .em dnoyeb si
elims t’nac I .hcnurc
,dnuora kcits ll’I“
,wen gnihtemos neht dnA
?rotidE ?rohtua nA
taht retfa wef rehtona neht dna
,hguoht ,nwo ym nO
.denigami dah I naht rehguot erew yeht tub ,ti denodnaba I erofeb rac ym fo edisni eht pu hsals ot ysae ytterp eb dluow ti thguoht dah I
tlef sevlesmeht ekam
,delbuod ylraen ereh yats ym htiW  .yppah s’eh dnA
”.tsael ta ,os epoh I
.knuj yb demusnoc ylwols gnieb fo
puc og-ot citsalp a sbarg dna yawa spets ehs ,ydaets m’I erus s’ehs ecnO
a yawa worht ot fi sa daeh ym ekahs neht ,nigeb I ”,esoppus I“
.yako eb lliw yxes elttil a gnieb ebyaM .wonk t’nod I
ll’I dna ,sexat eldnah dna skoob eht nuR“ .tnetnoc gnidnuos ,syas eh ”,eruS“ ”?sexat roF ?tner flaH“ .ti pleh t’nac I ,hgual I
elttil os ,mih no tneps emit hcum os
”.ffo erom tib a tnaw uoy fi syad emos ksed eht ekat nac uoY
,srebmun fo deeps mlac eht dna gnimoorg thgit ehT
.dessim evah dluohs I
,ti pans ssel hcum ,drac eht raet ot pirg a fo hguone teg t’nac I ,sdlof detaeper etipsed dna ,tsal ot dengised ,yltnerappa ,era sdrac DI
.gnihtyreve ,xat ytreporp fo erahs taht ,seitilitu—oiduts ym gniniatniam fo tsoc eht eciwt srevoc ,em rof ”,tner flaH“ .doog si ssenisuB
.skool ecaf ym woh enigami ylno nac I
.ruf ym evahs saw rolrap dom eht ta enod d’yeht gniht tsrif ehT
.deltsirb sreksihw dna derab hteet
tnereffid gnihtemos
,reh fo tnecs eht ,etoyoc ehT
.yawyna ffuts eht htiw derevoc era swap yM
”?sruoy era sgnitniap esohT .tihs yloH“ .kcuF
,rac eht otni dekcut saw ti woN .neeb dah ti rO
,dna loohcs hgih retfa tib a
.od ot gnihtemos swap ym evig ot tsuj
,regnol tnemom a em ta snirg aroruA ,detlit daeH
”.ffuts taht ,sexat elif ,skoob ruoy nur nac I
.efil suoiverp ym dnuownu I nehw derutcip d’I tahw t’nsi—
.bos a ni pu thguac s’ti hguoht ,hgual delgnarts a eganam I
,don I ”?edisni uoy eeS
.noitanidrooc seriuqer ,hguoht ,triks ehT
ym
…eb ot sah ereht ,hguoht ,yad eht gnirud éfac eht hguorht gniog elpoep eht lla htiW
,knis eht ni depmud era selttob llip tub
.nosaes-ffo fo elddim eht ni ereh yllaer t’nerew tub
.dnah no hguone naht erom dah I tub
.esrap ot tnemom a sekat ti dna siht yb detoof-gnorw m’I
,edacsac sti seunitnoc gof negortin ehT
.ereht ni diulf hguone s’ereht epoh ot evah tsuj I os
.munrets ym tsniaga nwo reh fo ssik a htiw sdnopser aroruA
.sthguoht ym htiw enola gnieb
,krow ta htnom a did yllautca I naht ssel derdnuh-neetfif ekam ot dedneterp gnivah em yb depleh t’nsaw siht dna
.emalf yb tilkcab
.delpmur htob er’yehT
stekcop fo ytilitu eht rof triks eht htiw norpa krow ym gniraew ot nekat d’I—
t’nod I ecno roF
:dnaltroP morf tuo syaw a er’eW
.trapa gnitfird dna ,rehtegot thgin a ,setad owT
.yletaidemmi otno hctal dluow ralgrub a hcihw ,VT a evah eW
,pu taht kool dluoc I .tfihs-txetnoc
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
nees d’I hcum taht—skeehc devahS
.yadot em tog tahw s’taht kniht I“
.mih tsurt ot evah tsuj I os ,eromyna evird t’nod I
”.sseug I ,yas ot bmud sleef tI
.yldnik ti gniyas tub elttil gniyas
,skcor etihw-klahc fo ssem delgnat a
,emalf ynit eht evoba esnecil s’revird ym gnirb ylluferac I ,swap gnikahs ym llits ot gnilggurts dna htaerb ym gnidloH
,tsrif ta ti otni ytterp erew I dna derraJ
”.yako s’tI .llihc ,yeh ,yeH“
,sksa eh ,ffo ti hsurb ot tuoba m’I sa tsuJ
,em ot txen dnuorg eht no talf ti yal ot elbat eht ffo gnitniap eht tfihs ylluferac I sa reffo I ”,ekil smees ,haeY“
.taes tekcub eht fo tuo em pleh ot ydaer
”.ereht syawla tsuj
.roolf eht otno dna elbat eht revo gniwolf
,evird daor-trid eht otni gnillup ,syas aroruA ”?pu s’tahW“
.elims snartal a fo seiromeM
,klaw uoy gnittel m’I yaw oN“
.em rednu morf tuo sbmil
.dluow ralgrub a wenk I tub ,ffuts eht rof erac t’ndid I
,repap fo skcats dna skoob htiw dellif s’ti
”.stinu eht fo emos gninaelc-peed pleh ruoy geb ylbaborp ll’I
.edis eht ot ffo gniggalf liat s’flow eht
.won gnoleb uoy ekil sleef tI
.dilos gnihtemos fo hcraes ni tevud eht ta gnihctulc swap ,tnelis llaf I
”.si sub a no enola gniyrc lufwa woh wonk I swonk ssendoog dna
ti dna ,ssem a s’efil yM .yadot ssem a hcus tsuJ
”.uoy er’uoY .aroruA m’I“
.detailimuh oot dnuos ot ton gniyrt ,yas I ”,seY“
,niks eht ot nwod tsomla ruf nworb enif gnittuc—
.yad eht tuohguorht egnahc dna evom elpoep hcihw ni syaw eht gniwollof
”.liaj fo tuo yats ot tnaw I fi toN“
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
”…reward eht morf yenom eht lla laets ,pu sriahc eht tup ,yawa doof eht lla tup ,nwod gnihtyreve epiW“
.gel ym tsniaga ni dekcut
.nwot eht hguorht ciffart fo wolf dna bbe eht hctaw ot gnitseretni s’tI
.)tibahni won I hcihw fo eno ,kcab ni snibac moor-eno elttil eht dna( stinu eht ot evird eht gniriaper tuo s’eh ,yllausU
.yad yreve reh hctaw I tub
serutcip ni erofeb ti nees d’I
.gniht eht fo dir gnieb fo feiler eht ebyam ro ,thguac gnieb ylraen fo llirht eht saw ti spahreP .yddig
,ffuts gnitniap ym fo lla rof demialc d’I hcihw
.yats ot sah lla sihT
,ytitnedi dlo ym htiw gnigagne naem dluow taht ecnis ,eman ym egnahc neve t’nac I
,gnihtemos yas ot hguoht sa htuom reh snepo ,lortnoc rednu gniyrc ym nettog ev’I retfa ,dna
.ssik eht otni nael tsuj I nehT
,rekrad semoceb ecnelis yM
—yrros m’I ,deksa ev’dluohs I
.hcum taht llet nac I tub
efil ym fo erew ereht strap tnereffid eht lla tuoba gnikniht emit fo tol a tneps I
railimaf htob ,srae reh fo tlit eht ,elzzum reh fo epahs ehT
.deirc ylbisiv t’nevah I erus ekam ot rorrim eht ni gnikeep
.llif ot em rof stiaw ehs ecnelis tnatcepxe nA
,rorret htiw dellif ooT
,tnemtrapa eht fo sessap ralucric ,wols ni ti dniwnu I
:htiw laed ot ysae si lesae yM .esle enoyna no
,nioc a fo ezis eht gnihtemos ot
.reh tsniaga ni em gniward s’ehs neht dna ,reh rednu morf tuo sgel reh sedils ehs sa noitom gnikcor nevenu elttil a s’erehT
,desnet selcsum ,gninrub seye
,ettal a sredro dna ytriht xis dnuora ni stfaw ehS
:era ew ereht neht dnA
.epacsdnal enihtnirybal a ni tsol si neht dna ,gniraes snrut neht ,dloc htiw sdael niap ehT
.yb og ot gnihtyna si ecniw reh fi ,ylthgit oot raf—
.niaga tsenrae ni gniyrc detrats ev’I ”…yeh—
”.retsam ,gniht eruS .eniF“
.retsaf on dna evif-ytxis ta daor eht nwod gnipmub era uoy nehw od ot draH .yrotsih tuohtiw
.niaga gnilbbab trats tsuj t’nod I os ,flesym ecap I ”.aroruA ,yrroS“
,kcab dehtooms sreksihw htiw kool desufnoc yleugav a detpoda s’madA ,pu kool I nehw dna ,tnatcepxe ot
.saw I ohw s’taht
.ti pans nac I ebyam taht hguone citsalp eht eugitaf ot tpmetta na ni taht dna yaw siht ti esaerc I dna ,tsael ta ,ti dneb nac I
.ni flesym tel dna—
.yllacitegolopa niaga kcab srae reh syal neht ,taht ta hgual a fo krab trohs a sevig aroruA
.eganam nac I sa ylteiuq sa derebmemsid si flehskoob ehT
.citenerf neht ,ysub semoceb ti ,ruoh na nihtiw tub
,kcab dennip sraE
.ecnatsbus on htiw niht repaP .repap…tsuj m’I
,hguoht ,em rof hcum oot eb ot tog tuo dellac eb dna pu ssem d’I taht yteixna ehT
.etercnoc erom gnihtemos drawot dedaeh ylwols dah tub ,eninac dna ralugna
,rehtruf drawpu swap reh gnigde erofeb regnol tnemom a setatiseh etoyoc ehT
.tekram eht fo tol gnikrap eht ,teerts eht ssorca ,dna tol gnikrap eht revo tuo skool wodniw eno ,tfel reh oT
eman fo tnemhcatta na
,yaw elbignat yrev a ni ,enod ev’I tahw fo em sdnimer ti
rehtegot yal eW .tnecs yrev reH
eippih a ekil gnikool ,sdom ydob
”.kcab og ot regae s’ohw lrig eht ekil mees t’nod uoY ?he
.roloc gnicrofnier spahrep ro
.rednaw ot tsuj nwot otni gnidaeh neve saw I won tub
.sesion tfoS ”.mM“ ”?mM“ .nigeb I ”…hu oS“
.eb dluoc niap etacirtni woh nwonk reven d’I
.sredluohs reh dnuora pu smra ym gnidils
.pirt sub ecnatsid-gnol a no neeb reven d’I
ew…erew uoy tuB“ .thguac
.ruf ym hguorht senil werd eson reh yaw eht
.gurhs a otni ti nrut dna ,rof gniog eb dluohs I tahw t’nsi ssenregae ediced neht ,ylregae don I ”.haeY“
.riahc kced eht otni rehtruf gnitlem neht ,nwod gnippolp ,daeh sih sekahs dna shgual madA
.erom tib a tuo pleh ot retfa thgiN yrratS ot kcab daeh neve nac I ,dedeen s’ti fI
;ti tuoba noissucsid oN .ti nruteR
.gniht laicos a yltsom s’ti ,tniop taht tA
.etoyoc eht rof ecalp otni sgniht kcilc ot smees ytivitca na hcus fo ytinadnum naiditouq ehT ”.naem I
”.ereht gnitteg er’uoy tub ,tib yknup eht otni worg ot elihw a uoy kooT .haey ,oot tahT“
,gab egabrag eht otni kcab drac depraw dna rethgil eht gniffuts ,yas I ”,yrroS“
.lio ekil dnuora sedils tI
.gniod er’uoy lla s’taht tsurt I dna ,yas uoy ,yawa teg ot ereh tuo er’uoY
.yug teiuq a tsuj osla s’eh tub ,ti ot noituac fo tnemele na ylniatrec saw erehT
.emit siht suovren erom
,srekaeps esuoh eht no pop eidni tfos eht ffo nrut I
.ti ta tsaf m’I tsael ta tub ,tif driew a si llit eht gninnur tnatnuocca nA
.wons fo gnillems niap etihw-klahc
,elbitpecrepmi emaceb yeht ecno dna
,secnalg derahs on s’erehT
.tsrif ta no pu dekcip t’ndah I hcihw ,yug doog a s’eH
”?ekil kool ti seod tahW
”.elbuort ni t’nia uoy
.seiromem dlo tsniaga sehsurb taht tnemevom a
stib pu nrot tsom eht no ruf gnirettacs
”.naem I ,drac dlo ym ekil dekool tsuJ“
,eci dna yeksihw fo sraj htiw sriahc ruo otni kcab elttes htob ew erofeb ,em ta eci fo tekcub elohw eht worht ll’eh hguoht sa sekam madA
reh tuoba erom tuo dnif nac uoY
.pu esnet dna tloj I
,sleep ananab dna sdnuorg eeffoc eht htiw ni ti ssot dna esnecil eht pu raet ot dednetni dah I
.tnemssarrabme ni deyalps srae ,em ot nwod snworf etoyoc ehT
.nwot llams a llits s’ti dna ,yad eno yna no elpoep esoht llA
.riahc sih fo kcab eht tsniaga sgurhs eh dna snetfos noisserpxe s’retto ehT
.seot debbew gniyalps ,tuo sgel sih sehcterts dna siht ta shgual madA
.egabrag taht otno
.reh ot yllacitegolopa elims dna rethgiarts pu dnats I
,elttil a daeh reh stfil aroruA ”.wonk t’nod I“
,erom ecno pu tis ot dewolla ma I dna dehsinif si nwodtnuoc tsal eht retfA
.seiromem deirub no gniggut
.yad eht fo trats eht ta tekcop a otni tellaw eht kcut em edam tahw yas t’nac I
ehca swap yM  .hgis a no
.lla dna detacude m’I
:yhw suoivbo saw ti ,tsrif tA
”.ti ni ’ecilop‘ drow eht dah enildaeh ehT“
dna delgnatnu triks ym teg spleh etoyoc eht sa bos dna naom ot eunitnoc tsuj I os
.daeh ym ekahs I ”…m’I ,yrroS“
.daeh ym fo kcab eht drawot sreksihw ym morf yawa gnitaidar
.rebmun ytiruces laicos on ,tiderc on ,tnuocca knab on ,slliks deifirev on ,yrotsih on htiW
.tsael ta ,rehtegot stnemom erom wef A
,rohtua na si nosidaM
.reh…yrev si rac s’aroruA  .don tsuj I os
;gnitrofmoc os lla s’ti
,detrats nosaes erofeb ereh tog uoY
”.ereh dnuor‘ krow emos od nac uoy fi flah ni ti tuc ll’I“
.gnilbbab fo maerts ym ffo tuc ot eciov reh gnisiar ,syas ehs ”!yeh ,aohW“ “—
,si ehs ereht tub ,neht yb nepo rood eht tog ev’I
.reh ot kcab maeb I
,em drawot kcab seirruh tar ehT
piteson looc reh dna
”,raeppasid ot snosaer evah lla eW“
,tey ,evom ot woh tuo derugif t’nsah ydob yM
.msinahcem gnipoc a naht tibah a fo erom emaceb ti ,hguoht ,nooS
.nwot gnivael erofeb seitnap wen yna barg ot thguoht t’ndah I
,noitasnes gnitsal enO
,gniyrc hcum os retfa dluow s’enoyna sa llew sa tuoba gniod si eson yM
”?hcum taht degnahc I evaH“ ”.sgnitniap ruoY“
,erusaelp fo llews gnisir A
neeb dah ti gnol woh tuoba gnihtemos ,eman dlo ym dna ”ecilop“ tuoba gnihtemos—elcitra na fo espmilg taht gninrut emit erom naem tsuj d’taht tub ,klaw dluoc I
.seye sih fo tuo rufdaeh tpmeknu gnipeek feihcrek a htiw loots a no gnittis
”.ti did I yhw wonk t’nod I dezilaer I ,ti was I nehw ,kniht I dna
,ksa I ,sreh revo dekcut elzzuM .ecaep dna
.oga ruoh flah a ylno
,wap s’lrig a gnidloh ereht gnidnats ,loof a gnikooL
,stsaerb ym evoba tsuj tis ll’tI
.hguoht ,ti ni sehtolc fo htrow s’yad a tog tsuj s’tI .ni
.sedis ym pu yawflah esuap swap s’aroruA dna ,pu esnet dna sthguoht gnirednaw ym morf ssenerawa ot tloj I
”ah ah ,haey hO“ nA
.swodniw eht tuo serats dna riahc eht otni kcab selttes ehs ,retaw ados eht dehsinif s’ehs ecnO .aet eht neht ,retaw ados eht sknird neht
,ecaf ym fo otohp eht htaeneb elttes wolg esuffid eht gnittel
ffo dnim ym gnikaT
,gnilffins llitS
.ruf ym yb delffum si eciov wol ,tfos reH
sgnileef eud-tsap esoht llA
.rewsna t’nod I ”?tfel s’tahW“
.gniyrc ydaerla d’I taht tcaf eht dnim reven
.yna gniraew deppots ylegral d’I
sa dnif nac uoy hcihw
,erofeb tekramrepus yknid eht ot enog tsuj d’I
,kcapkcab a ni yawa dekcut xob yrlewej ym fo stnetnoc eht dna roolf eht no dessot seohs htiw
.yletaidemmi srotagitsevni ffo deppit ev’dluow tahT
.nafetS dna ,esruoc fo ,madA s’erehT
.dnuownu yletelpmoc t’nsi efil yM
tsuj nac I ,kniht ot evah t’nod I
.dloh ot DI na neve ton
.nirg yekoj a htiw yteixna nwod gnipmat ,don I
.sdrow rof gnihcraes ,elbmum I
,meht neewteb ssik a ecalp ot drawrof nael I os
.hguoroht kool ot evah I tub
,hguoht ,yawyna neht yb ereh tuo flah saw traeh yM .su…hu
,srae reh era ees yllaer nac I lla ,wol ylbatrofmocnu elzzum ym gnikcut tuohtiW ”?oot ,yako si sihT“
.ylgnimrasid swap reh pu gnidloh ,shgual aroruA
.depmarc si taes ehT
.ecin saw ti ,oN“
.yteixna level-wol naht rehto gnihtemoS .esle gnihtemoS
.tnatnuocca na saw I ,naem I…nac I ,hU“
.ereht gnihton s’erehT“
esrow hcum nees dah ohw xof a fo tnemegdelwonkca derit eht htiw em deteerg dah revird sub ehT
,keehc hcae no srab eerht dna
.ni no daeh dna skoob fo elip eht revo ylteiuq pets I
devom I ecnis reward sehtolc naelc ym sa esactius ym gnisu neeb ev’I
,elbatrofmoc si ecnelis eht dna
.ecaps gniknird sa etats remrof sti ot snruter su neewteb elbat eht fo lesae s’lesaew-roop yM
.esruoc fo ,edisni morf gnihtoN .esactius a dna
,retaw ados eht neht
syek ym rof tekcop norpa ym ni hsif I ,ereht ecnO
”.mmM“ ”.wonk uoy ,gnitniap uoy ees ot doog’S“
.bat rieht elttes ew dna ylkciuq tnih eht no pu skcip elpuoc xof ehT
.tluciffid sevorp niaga roolf eht otno gnilbbow tuohtiw thgirpu eb ot yaw a gnidniF
.sevren delzzarf ym rof duol oot kraps eht fo pans eht
.htuom reh fo renroc eht gninrut nirg a fo tnih a
.ecnelis suovren ot
.llew hA .derraJ rooP
.gnibbos ym si emit fo egassap eht gnibircsed gniht ylno ehT
,haey ,dehcuot ev’I
.gniht eruS“ ,sgurhs nafetS
,)rolrap siht nesohc d’I nosaer eht gnieb taht(
.taht retfa gnihton saw erehT
.etats dnuorg sti otni nwod kcab selttes nwot eht dna
”.daeh ym fo kcab eht drawot tuo gnidaerps
,draobyek eht ta emit hcum oS
efil sihT .efil-non sihT
tpmetta na tsael ta etaerc ot
.tnemevom neddus ym ta pets-flah a kcab gniltrats aroruA
.enod selit gniliec eht fo driht a tuoba nettog ev’I
.og stel ehs erofeb no gnidloh m’I erus gnikam
.sredluohs ym fo edis rehtie ot detnalp swap
,flesym mlac ot shtaerb gniplug wef a ekat dna ffo liart I
.em nihtiw skcilc gnihtemos neht dna
,flesti nwot eht ni evil ohw esoht tub
.nialp erew dnarb eht fo skram tnrub-rezeerf eht ,skeew wef tsrif eht rof dna ,devahs ylhserf llits saw ecaf ym ,nwot ot tog I nehw
.yzarc gnikcuf gnikooL
,ta kool ot thgirb oot nus a ,etihw ,ereS
lufthgiled a s’ereht ,VT eht revo esrever I nehW
.yeksihw ta wap sih gniyrt won si dna mur morf no devom sah retto ehT
.trams t’nsi taht neve
,etoyoc snart ,yepom a stnaw eno on dna
”?neht ,tseretni ruoy deuqip ti tuoba
.yssem sgniht ekam I etar eht htiw pu peek t’nac eh dna ,sdradnats s’derraJ htiw pu peek t’nac I sa ,esruoc fo ,taen oot toN
,thgiN yrratS fo renroc eht ni devreser tub lla elbat a sah ehS
,mM“ ”.enohp eht no enoemoS .enoemos ot ti tuoba gniklat saw eH
,dnuora ssalg nwo ym lriws dna etatiseh I
.gabaet dnoces eht rof retaw toh fo top rehtona dna retaw ados rehtona sredro ehs ,noon tA
,eman ym gnola esaerc ot yrassecen egarevel eht evah t’nod I
,seunitnoc ehs dna ,don I
,rethgil citsalp paehc a
.reh ekil ,roiretxe elpmis sti htaeneb no gniog tol a tog s’ti tub ,yssem ton s’ti ;si gab reh sa
,seenk dna spih ym ni ssenilbbow eht lepsid ot gniyrt
.sriahc kced ni gnittis elihw mur fo elttob a flah gnirahs otni denrut sah ,revewoh ”,stnemegnarra gnissucsiD“
,saw I ohw wonk uoy dna
.tnemtrapa eht fo erac ekat ot emoh daeh I ,rolrap dom eht morF
.daeh ym ekahs I sa shgual tar ehT
,dezingocer neeb gnivah ta rorret ,sedisni ym ni gnivac raef leef
.sdrow htiw ecaps rof yekcoj yeksihw edamemoh dna eci enihcam eci ,htuom ym nI
,ylraelc erom yas ot ezeerf niarb eht evarb dna eci eht no nwod hcnurc I ”?hE“ ”?gnosae‘ ffo ni ’il s’ahW“
.yako eb dluow ti ekil dna
.neewteb sdrow tuo eke ot evah I ,won yrd ,niaga pu kcip sbos eht sA ”.gnihton s’erehT“
tfel yna evah I desirprus m’I—
,ti deyortsed d’I .gnitsixe regnol on efil taht no sdneped nwot siht ni ereh ecnetsixe yrev yM
mur fo hcni rehtona em sruop madA
,hsuhs ro ooc t’nseod ehS
.aroruA s’ereht neht dnA
”?nwot eippih a ni dirg eht ffo gnivil lesaew yknup A“
.erutuf eht rof stnemegnarra ssucsid ot
.ssik eht morf yawa llup ot ylthgils daeh ym gnitsiwt ,rumrum I ”,tiaW“
.psarg reh otni gnixaler
,ti gnitleM .lla dna
.roolf eht tuoba yldrazahpah nwerts gnihtolc dna nepo deggut era srewarD
,deltrats skool ehS
.sreksihw fo gniltsirb eht dna srae fo gnikrep ehT
,emoh kcab rac denodnaba ym yb derettacs yal ti dellif ecno dah taht sdrac tiderc ehT
.taht tuohtiw yb teg nac uoY“
,gnivael erofeb eman ym degnahc ev’d’I ,ydal retrams a erew I fI
.emit elbuod ni sessik fo etuor reh gnicarter ,erom ecno drawrof thgiew reh gnitfihs yltnetni sa tsuj kcab serats aroruA
,shtnom neeb s’tI
.yawyna ,ereh ni yad drieW .hguone riaF“
.oot ,niaga gnitniap detrats ev’I
dnarg ytnewt fo yhs tsuJ .hsac neddih d’I
,nwot otni gnilkcirt trats sklof ,gninrom eht ni xis tuoba gnitratS
,elbavil ot esolc gnihtyna em gniyap ton s’eH
rotaluclac desahcrup-yltnecer ym no htam eht nar I
.ecniw a otni snrut elims eht dna
t’nod I ,yrros ,hU“
.weN .lamron ton ,lleW
kcapkcab a otni dekcap
”.aroruA si tog ev’ew lla ,haeY“
.niaga kaeps nac I erehw tniop eht ot teg ot setunim wef a em sekat llits ti tub
.siht si gniksa m’I tahw oS“ .snirg tsuj eH
,gnivahs eht fo segde eht leef dna ruf eht revo sdap ym hsurb d’I
t’nseod tI .sredluohs ym dnuora smra
.dil eht pu gnippilf ,retspmud eht ot revo hsad dna tekcop ym otni kcab tellaw ym ffuts I
.tnemetatsrednu na fo tiB“
,enihcam osserpse eht morf nees sa elbat reh ta aroruA
.rorret dna tliug fo evaw gnisir a nwod wollaws ot evah I .sraey dna sraeY
,loohcs hgih fo sespmilg dna ,htaerb ym hctac ot gnitnaP .noitcennoc A
”?hguone eb taht lliw ,’ylluferac yrev‘ yas tsuj I fI“
,dael eht gnikat elbatrofmoc smees aroruA .tsal ta llitS
,ma I erehw em tog taht sgniht eht fo
.gnitnap flesym hctac ot ylno
.ssenmlac fo reenev eht hguorht gnikaerb
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,thgiN yrratS fo renwo eht tog ev’I won dna ,seitilibissop erom tuoba deksa d’I retfa gniklat emos did madA sseug I
.edit hgih woleb tsuj dnas fo sniarg s’ti
,boj a teg t’nac I .kcuF
.tsehc ym tsniaga erofeb sa delffum ,elggig a steg gnimriuqs ym dna ,gnileef fo tros hsilkcit a s’tI
yortsed ylluferac I
s’teL .revo llef uoy…hu uoY .tuo sgel ,no emoC“ .rab eht tsniaga kcab gninael m’I litnu pu em revel spleh ehS
.esruc tfos a neht dna ,deruop gnieb retaw naht xelpmoc erom gnihtemos fo dnuos a
dna s’madA ot kcab sub eht fo kniht I
.em fo edis rehtie ot nottoc fo sloop ni gnillips
.oot elor taht otni gnippils m’I esoppus I
.owt txen eht rof seirtnasaelp elpmis neht
.ruf revo pu trihs gnihcni
,egarag dehcatta eht htiw edis eht rof artxe diap dna xelpud a flah detner d’eW
,enihcam osserpse naelc-ydaerla eht nwod gnipiw htiw flesym gniysub
.ysub teg sgniht fi llit eht nur em tel ot dereffo neve eH
.rewsna na evah t’nod I
.snoisacco elpitlum no erom ro ruoh na rof daor trid a fo ecnanetniam dna peekpu eht tuoba em htiw deklat s’eh
”,hguone noos etihw nrut ll’tI“
,railimaf gnihtemoS
,dirg eht ffo tub lla sboj gnikrow—sihT
;oot sevom aroruA
.swollip fo elip eht tsniaga kcab gnippolf
ytimrone reehs eht ta tub ,dnim ,niap eht ta toN
,swap ym drawot stniuqs ,sdon ehS
”.t’now uoy tcepxe ot tseb s’ti tub ,thgim uoY
.ecafrus sti ta yllautceffeni elbbarcs ylno spit walc ym dna
.tsenrae ni hgual I ,siht tA
.yretsym a fo gnihtemos saw erofeb em depacse dah siht woH
.devahs saw I erofeb nib s’pohs dom eht morf tib a nevE
.og eno ni puc eht fo tser eht hsinif dna ,ma ylurt I ytsriht woh ezilaer I ,wollaws I nehW
,pu sesnet yletaidemmi aroruA
.ti htiw gnilddif peek I hcum woh nevig ,doog si hcihw
,snworb citsalp ehT
.thgiew reh gnitfihs aroruA
”,yrp t’now I .sserts on ,yeH“
.shgiht ym neewteb elzzum derepat a fo yromem taht dna—
,yawa detlem evah sliated gniyfitnedi eht hcum dna ecaf ym fo egami eht
.nosaes-ffo eht llits s’ti em desimorp s’eh tub ,tey t’nevah yehT
,gnizzub ot wap elohw ym sdnes tnilf eht tsniaga leehw eht fo psar ehT
.stniop owt neewteb nward enil a dna
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”ecnaraeppasiD“
.tsenrae ni snway ehS
.hceeps-non eht fo tib
,yawa tup era sehtolC
,I naht rellat raf lesaew a ,ecilpmocca sih htiw gnola tar eht s’erehT
,detaeh naht rednet erom ,ssik lanif eht rof pu snael aroruA
.oot ylrae stes nus eht ,nosaes eht ni etal sihT
.taht otni hcum oot daer ot ton yrt I tub
,gniog sessenisub eht lla peek dna hguorht pots sniatnuom eht ot pu gnidaeh skloF
.mrof reh fo ssentfos ehT
,skeehc ym fo ruf yltsirb ,trohs eht revo wap ym bur I
selcsum fo noitaxaler neht ,noitcartnoc A
.wap dereffo reh ekat dna ,lufhsab gnileef ,nirg I
.gnilims s’ehS .aroruA ”.yeH“
tuo noitcafsitas ehtaerb I os
.deciton neeb evah dluow gnissim gnihtyna esuaceb ,denosaer I ,enif ylbaborp saw sihT
.hguoht ,ereh dnuora boj doog a od uoY .hguone riaF“
snoitacol citnamor erom ot yaw rieht no syawla er’yehT
.emoh kcab sub ro klaw I emit yreve reh tuoba kniht I tub ,pohs eht fo tuo reh nees reven ev’I
niaga sdnarb esoht gnola gnisaet si
.hctaw ecin s’derraJ htiw gnola
.tnemom a rof rehto hcae ta ,gnidneherpmocnu ,erats eW
.meht pota nwod-edispu sriahc gnikcats
.ekorts dna hsurb ot ,hcuot ot
.txen si nehctik ehT
,ylevitressa erom em revo nwod snael dna ,ngis a sa ti nekat evah ot smees aroruA
.nekat seitrebil on htiw mrof ot eurt tub
.evil ot evah ll’I
.hsac htiw stekcit sub yub nac uoy tuB
,yako s’tI“ .madA fo tnorf ni cinap ylbisiv ot ton yrt I
gniht taht seod eH
,mra reh ssorca sregnif ym hsurb I ”.I saw rehtieN“
”?no ti gnirb gnihtynA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw setirW oykaM
,hsac tub gnihtyna em reffo t’ndluoc uoY
.ni kcab werg ti sa pu dekcip I tibah a
.etsah ni enod lla saw ti hguoht sa kool ot swalc ym htiw dedderhs dna sserttam eht fo eerf dellup era steehs deb ehT
,rehtegot gnihtyna neddih reven d’ew ,I dna derraJ
.boj a teg t’nac I tuB
.kcab ym dnuora mra na sekans ehs ,rehtruf pu parts s’gab reh gniggurhS
,ereh devil I skeew owt tsrif eht rof yliad sdon degnahcxe eW
.em ot pu kcab neht
.efil wen siht yojne
.swap fo serutseG
.etihw ni gniworg won ,ruf tfos ,lamron yb decalper neeb ylegral dah sehctap dednarb ,depsirc ehT
,dab os efil fo tuo dedeen uoY
,toof ym rednu ti hsurc dna gab citsalp a ni ssalg a tup ot si ytsah gnikool ot noissecnoc yM
.yrdnual did I emit yreve riap dlo taht gniees saw ,hguoht ,yrettij em dah tahW
.daetsni eulb eht rof tnew I tub ,knip detseggus ehS
.erus ekam ot doog s’ti ,llitS
.od I naht erom shgiew
.gnihgual ,ffo em stuc etoyoc eht
.triks delpmur fo elip a revo tnorf ym gnola em ta pu skool ehs sa gniggaw
.dnuof eb ot erehwon eb ll’eh ,gnisolc rof ereht eb ot evah t’nseod eh fI
.yaw eht fo tuo ti peek ot ffo trihs ym gniggut eM
,eno yb eno strap esoht lla ot dnuora tnew dna etad a tes tsuj I neht dnA“
,em suhT .dnuora peek ot
.em evoba epahs ralugna ,krad a ees nac I tub
.ruf sih fo nworb eht tsdima ruf etihw fo snrettap gnilioc elpmis gnilaever ,eveels sih pu sehcnub dna mra sih tuo sehcterts eH .syas lesaew eht
”.tol a gnits ot gniog si siht ,oN“ .don I
,esactius ym fo kcab eht ni tellaw dlo ym nihtiw dekcut ,eman lagel lautca ym gniraeb tnemucod lagel lautca nA
.skeew wef tsal eht revo sehctab hguorht gnilcyc neeb ev’eW
.seil htiw ti deretnuoc d’I ,elihw a roF
;erehwesle dneps ot elttil os
,railimaf sleef ti
.nwot llams a hcus s’tI
.ssenetihw otni spraw dna sedaf esaerc eht gnola kni eht hguoht
gnivil a rof seod ehs tahw rof eerged egelloc reh sesu yllautca ohw wef eht fo eno eb ot emosewa tlef ti dna
,htaerb reh fo htmraw eht—
,tnanmer emos ssorca emoc I emit hcaE
.otni gninnur peek I euqinhcet ’ecnelis‘ taht esu ot tpmetta dna riahc kced eht otni kcab elttes I
.thgirtuo gnikcinap morf em speek pu-wollof fo kcal eht dna ,hguoht ,mrof fo rettam a erom si esruc elgnis A
snioj ti erehw llaw eht tsniaga yllacimhtyhra pat pitliat sih eht sa hctaw I dna ,sworruf worb s’nafetS ”.wonk t’nod I .was rO
”.sgnitniap ruoy saw ti tuB .erew uoy ohw
,gniltsirb liat dna gninettalf morf srae ym peek ot tseb ym od I
.ydal doog a er’uoY
.tner ruoy evlah
.tnecrep derdnuh a ot denrut
,elit knalb a htiw emoh em tnes dna pu dekrep ,renwo eht ,nafetS
.efil taht fo tuo dedeen I“
cinap fo shtnom ynam oS .aroruA fo
.thginot flesym fo ssem a fo hguone edam ev’I tub ,retaw eht nwod plug tsuj ot tnaw I
.em evoba tnelis syats ehS ”.ffuts
.rethgil eht fo emalf wol eht yb ffo tnrub kni eht
”.klaw ot deen t’noD .hguoht ,sub eht ekat nac I
.deffucs dna wolley
.ereht gnihton tsuJ .sdileye ym fo edisni eht ees ot gniyrt ekil s’tI .ereht gnihton
.raef otni thgiarts demorac sihT
-----seivom rof desu reve ylno ew taht gniht neercs talf a—
,deltrats gnikool ereht lesaew eht
.eman on htiw tnatnuocca na erih ot gniog si eno oN
dna psag gniredduhs A .seiromem fo
.kcab gninael ylluferac erofeb emit erom tib a em sevig aroruA
ti gniyas emit drah a evah dluow tub ,ti kniht nac I—
.éfac eht ta ereh m’I
”.deklaw ro sub eht neddir reve ylnO
.sklaw gnikat detrats I won tub
,etoyoc yhs dna ykwag taht fo seiromem nwod hsup I
.triks dna trihs ym revo nwod kool I
.rehtruf pu esnet ot si eganam nac I lla tub ,yawa hsup ot yrt I
”,enif er’uoY .on ,oN“ “—
”,mhmM“ ”?pu gnisolc yako uoY .neht ,ylrae ffo ekat ll’I ebyaM
.yromem ot gnicafrus
,esolc pu gnitanicsaf si elpoep fo tnemevom ehT
.ecnelis s’ti ,no neht morF
,spahrep ,tcafitra gnitseretni na saw tI
.flesym rof gnikooc rof ytnelp s’taht evots renrub-owt a htiw moor eht ni ettenehctik elttil a s’ereht dna
.gnilims ,sksa ehs ”?thgir ,s’madA“
.elit eht fo segde eht drawot niht-reksihw emaceb taht sehcnarb otni gnittilps sbmil
.ffo siht llup ot elba eb yllautca yam I ,tihs yloH
.erom gniyas pu nevig ev’I
.daeh ym ni revo dna revo—
erom si thgiew reh tub ,flesreh seirrac ehs yaw eht s’ti ebyaM
,haeY“ ”?retteb gnioD“
,ni sllor edit ehT
.elbapacseni sleef kcurt hsart eht fo tuo gnillaf ro retspmud eht fo tuo gnippils ti fo thguoht eht tub
,ssalc elddim-rewol naht rehgih reven
.pu ti gnirevoc naht rehtar ecafrus der krad taht nihtiw gnitniap
,seno lesaew ot esolc era ,gnirevocsid m’I ,snoisserpxe rettO
.eeffoc dlo ylbaborp—
”?lla ta ton naem uoY .yrroS“
.ecnef kcab eht dna thgiN yrratS neewteb evorg ynit a gnimrof ,rehto hcae ot esolc oot detnalp neeb evah taht seert eerht ,reh fo tnorf nI
,dnuora smra ym parw ot gnihtemos
,ylroop os tif yehT
.esacwollip repap dezitinas a ni wollip a tsniaga nwod elzzum ym sdloh rehtonA
.flesym tuoba ,derraJ tuobA .swen eht no gniht taht was I
.gnirewsna erofeb daor eht otno denrut dna tops reh fo tuo desrever s’ehs litnu stiaw aroruA
.taht dnoyeb raf ,raf neht dna
.erom sreksihw eht esu tub
”,sexat“ yas I etunim ehT
.sderdnuh wol eht ni rebmun ylbaborp ,nwot eht era ohw
;lla retfa ,tuoba yrrow ot deen I taht em tuoba gniht gniyfitnedi rewef eno s’tI
.yeksihw fo hcni rehtona flesmih gniruop ,selbmum madA
.ytilibats fo tib emos
,emoh kcab deirt I“
.DI ym morf erutcip eht was I .eman ym was I
.thguac saw I ecno senildaeh eht enigami ylno nac I
,em naht reggib s’ehS
,hcnul kcas a tuo llup ll’ehs syad emoS
”?taht od uoy d’yhW“ ,ksa I
.tnedifnoc era sekorts-hsurb yM .wen dna
.nirg sih htiw drawtuo eltsirb sreksihw sih dna pu skrep madA
,yaw taht ti evael ot nesohc d’I dna ,ydnugrub em ot nevig neeb dah elit ehT
.rac eht fo repmub tnorf eht fo yhs tsuj seceip ot srettalc gniht ytekcir ehT
,efil dlo ym tuoba kniht dluoc I sgniht eht lla gniniatnoc tip kcalb A .gnihton dnuora
”.stnerap ym lla fo tsael
.tibah a emoceb s’ti ,llitS
.elit dnoces ym no gnikrow ma I ereh dna
,elzzun a fo gnihtemos otni noitom taht nrut ot gnippid elzzum
.duol oot sdnuos ti dna
,nwod kcab elttes ylpmis dna ,sdrow htiw ti llif ot hsur
”.uoy er’uoY .aroruA m’I tub
,tnelis dna llits stis tsuj eh erehw gniht taht seod tar ehT .flesym ot neve
.kni.oykam no
,ylevislupmoc wollaws I
,kcab semoc nirg yllis ylthgils tahT ”.ecin laeR
,tnecer tsom reh gnidulcni
”,hsac rof gnitruh t’nia uoy ekil mees uoY“
.oga sraey morf gnihtemos ekil
.eugnot evitnetta na dna elzzum a fo seiromeM
.sredluohs reh no swap ym tsuj s’ti litnu reh dnuora morf smra nwo ym pils I
,sessik fo liart eht
”.tbed fo tuo slesaew ,eman segnahc lesaeW“
.ssem eht dna edistuo ksud eht tsniaga ssenthgirb neddus eht ta htob ,egnirc dna sthgil eht no pilf I .si tsuj ehS
.looc gnitca rof hcum oS
,sesab rieht dnuora skram walc dezarc ylluferac hctarcs dna selop rieht no srekaeps eht revo pit I
,etoyoc eht ot ezigolopa ot nrut I .kcuF
.siht xif dna yrt ot emit evah I tsael tA
,rood eht nepo I nehw ereht s’aroruA
tnatnuocca na gnieB
,ylf nac uoy nehw elbaknihtnu si pirt sub yrtnuoc-ssorc A
”.gniveiht eb ot gnikool-emoselohw oot er’uoY
.nwod gnitnuoc s’enoemoS
.yvaeh naht gnitrofmoc
.flesreh htiw elbatrofmocnu os demees dah ehS
.roolf eht otno dna retnuoc eht revo sdrahs eht rettacs neht
,ti no kcab kool I nehw ,woN
.liatne d’taht tahw fo saedi revo gninrut ,daeh ym tlit I ”?kroW“
:ecnelis tnatcepxe ni dnats eW
.llew ylgnisirprus no gnitteg neeb evah I dna ,madA ,roteirporp ehT
,hcum oot hsac ym eye-edis t’nseod taht letoh yats-gnol a s’erehT .esruoc fo ,ereh yats nac I
riap eno ylno htiw em tfel siht ,yletanutrofnU
”.tigel gnieb tuohtiw dnarg gnihtyna dnif annog t’nia uoy ekil tnatnuoccA .dnarg t’nia tI
,tnatnuocca citsatnaf a saw I
.reh ot pu ylhsipeehs elims dna saw taht duol woh ezilaer I ”!oN“
.emit ot ecalp ot
.em selkcit rab eht dniheb evots eboda taht htiw denibmoc swodniw eht fo ytilacitcarpmi eht tuoba gnihtemoS
.taen s’gnihtyrevE
taht otni degassam liof munimula fo eceip a dna ,seye ym dnuora ruf eht otni deraems si yllej muelortep kciht A
.lla ta yrdnual eht deciton t’nsah ehs tub
,sremotsuc eht drawot yleugav serutseg eh
.thgin ta xis ta eeffoc gniredro elpoep ynam toN
.gniht emas eht detseggus madA“
.trihs ym evoba morf pu keep ll’ti ,esiwrehto tub
.ereh rac a ni neeb ev’I emit tsriF .gnikniht tsuJ“
.sevael nellaf eht htiw ni dexim srepparw repap dna snac delpmurc htiw ,ereht tserof ynit a saw erehT
,ereh tuo tog I ecno srossics ym dnif t’ndluoC“
.oga sraey ytnewt no hgin morf seiromeM
dnim ym gnillif eb ot smees tcatnoc lacisyhp fo noitaralihxe reehs ehT
,erew uoy ohw wonk I“ “—
.elihw a ni desu neeb t’ndah taht hsurb a dna cilyrca fo sebut ytsurc wef a htiw gnola
tekramrepus eht fo elsia ”slaitnesse“ eht tisiv ot dah d’I dna—
”.spoohw“ luferac yrev A
.os od ot yaw a dnif ot em rof
.niripsa naht gnitseretni erom gnihtemos rof gnitnuh saw enoemos ekil gnikool
.retspmud eht otni kcab gniht elohw eht gniluah erofeb
,ti dnif I sa noos sa tsomla yawa dnif I gnihtyreve worht I—
.tey aedi tseb ym ylbaborP
.ytitnedi elohw a saw tI
.eganam nac I tseb eht si hturt-flah A
.nogerO ot yaw eht lla
”.sseug I ,saw I erehw fo tuo dedeeN“
.mlac m’I .gnillifluf
.nwod nrot teg ot tsal eht si dna ,ecaps ym neeb dah egarag ehT
,su htiw pohs eht tuo esolc lliw aroruA ,deyats ev’I snoisacco wef eht nO
.em ediseb syal ehs erehw morf
,tnaw I nehw ”yxes“ og dluoc taht enO
.swap ym otni lewot pu-dellor a sesserp enoemoS
,ytriht-enin tuoba litnu ylidaets sbmilc ti ,ereht morF
.taerg oot saw detsixe regnol on taht efil a otni reep ot noitatpmet ehT
.yats-gnol eht ot kcab teg ot setunim net naht ssel su sekat ti sa
.koob reh morf yawa gnikool neve tuohtiw ffo mih spilf etoyoc ehT
.yrtemmys eht ekorb taht etihw fo snoitseggus eugav erew sevael ehT
,ytfarc yltcaxe t’nsi kool ehT
.nway a gnilfits dna eson tsniaga eson ,sdon ehS ”.emoh tuobA
—wonk t’nod I dna ,gniliec eht tniap em tel yehT
.gnilbmuf naht tsenrae erom
.sucof fo tniop ralugnis a
,gnitniap a fo hcteks A
.gnilf loohcs hgih A
eugnot emas taht
,edir sub eht no rulb ot nugeb ydaerla dah ”yhw“ ehT
.gniwolfrevo s’repmah eht tub
,senil degde-draH
.em ta selims aroruA
trihs ym fo eveels eht htiw ecaf ym ta epiws dna hgual I ”.toocS .no emoC“
,em gnidloh tsuj dna
.skeehc ym revo kcab gnihsurb fo erutseg eht htiw no ylrae hctiwt taht decalper I
”.sepahs ehT .senil ehT“
”.gniod thguac teg ot gniht driew a tsuj s’ti sseug I“
.thguoht I sa hcum sa etiuq siht rof deraperp t’nsaw I tub ,tsenoh eb ot ,detcepxe d’I tahw tuobA
.no pu dekcehc skeehc ym teg ot nwot ni pots gnimoorg enol eht ot derutnev neve I
:rof gnikool m’I tahw dnif I erofeb sgab egabrag niht s’pohs eht fo owt hguorht raet I
.swalc sih neewteb rae ym sehcnip dna tuo sehcaer eh ”,eilrig dnA
.timda ot detnaw d’I naht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gninnur on ,gniveiht oN
.pey ,ffo thgir detlob uoY“
.esaet elttil a tsuJ
,dnuos gnilgrug ,gnissih a s’erehT
.raeg gnipmac dlo ym etarecsive I
,skeehc ym ta llup niks tnrub-dloc gnileef ,elims ot yrt I ”.sseug I…hU“
.doog sdnuos ti tub ,eurt si siht kniht t’nod I
ycnegreme na ni elbanwap gnihtemos rof tpek , ecnatsni rof ,yrlewej eht—smeti lufesu wef a naht rehtO
.od nac yppah era ohw elpoep taht gniht a s’taht ebyaM .tnatcepxe osla tub
detniap I ffuts fo epyt eht tsuJ
.ereht ksed eht nur ot hcnul retfa s’madA ot kcab gnidaeh dna thgiN yrratS ta sgninrom gnikrow ot nekat ev’I
.eno tsal eht ta pu gnivom ot kcart trohs eht no saw dna seciffo APC wef a rof dekrow I .ti syojne dna
.tenretnI eht ffo gnihtemos denoitnem enoemos nehw wap ym ni hctiwt elttil a teg d’I ,ereh saw I shtnom wef tsrif eht roF
.meht fo skcab eht esopxe ot sedis eht ot doof dna sessalg gnihsup :stenibac dna egdirf eht fo ssap yrosruc a s’erehT
.tops sti ni eci fo tekcub eht gnicalper
.esruoc fo rettam a era ,tcepxe I ,secnelis reH
,erus dnuos t’nod I ”.seY“
.dnik eciov wol ,sksa ehs
,flesym yojne tsuj ot flesym llet I
tneb si lufmra yreve morf enO
eman a dna ,wolg mraw A
,yllacizziuq daeh reh stlit etoyoc ehT ”.enod lla m’I“
”?emoc woH .thgirla ,thgirlA“
gnileef em tfel sah retspmud eht yb retnuocne eht tuoba gnihtemoS
.lla ti evoba senot-eltsihw gniyalp etulf a dna
.enif s’taht ,llew hO
.tsenrae ni egnirc neht
:hturt-flah a htiw pu emoc dna
”?raeppasid uoy d’yhW“ ”?mM“ ”?uoy dnA“
.esaelp ,tnecrep net naht erom oN“ .shgual flow ehT
,tfel I nehw eb ot desu I ohw fo efil ym gnisnaelc fo boj doog a hcus enod d’I denigami d’I
.rac eht yb kcab sti nwod ti yal dna-
ruf eulb fo lioc eht ta esaet ot nwod gnippid
.egrahc sekat aroruA ,éfac eht morf ohce na sa spahreP
elbatrofmoc morf seog ecnelis ehT
”?oddik ,ereht thgirla uoY“
.ereht ”taht was I ,haeY“ a dna ereh
.muelonil no gnikcilc swalc htiw moor eht ssorca sdap
.tnuocca knab rehtona nepo t’nac I ,ecalp a tner t’nac I
,meti yb meti ,tsilkcehc a kcitnu ylwols I .saw I tahw
;kcalb ni etteuohlis reh htiw ,ydnugrub ,elit gniliec dna stniap eht no dekcol seye s’aroruA
”.gnitniap uoy ees ot doog s’ti dnA“
,esu dednetxe s’ti retfa wap ym ni nwod looc ot gnitrats yllanif si rethgil ehT
.stuotnirp pu gnikram ro seton gnikat rehtie syawla s’ehs tub ,krow rof seod ehs tahw tuo derugif reven ev’I
.efil suoiverp ym gnidniwnu fo ruoh taht no tneps I tahw naht ereh tog I ecno od ot tahw tuo gnirugif ygrene erom tneps ev’dluow I ,ydal retrams a erew I fI
”?nosaes ffo eht ni ekil ti s’tahW“
.gnipmac redisnoc neve ot hguone gnol retupmoc sih morf yawa flesmih llup reven ot derraJ detsurt I
,gninrub skeehc dednarb ylwen ym tuohtiw
.mhmM“ ”.elttil a kram eht ssim snaej dna strihs dnah-dnoceS .sseug I ,pu-teg eht gnissim tsuJ“
.elbbub dna rahc ot strats neht ,sgas
.skeehc ruoy nwod gniruop sraet
,ezag reh wollof I
.draobpilc a dna stuotnirp fo kcats a ro koob a rehtie dna nep a tuo sllup ehs ,retaw ados eht dehsinif s’ehs ecnO .aet eht neht
.aroruA“ “—er’uoy ,tiaW“
.rorret eht edih ot ti eht esu I dna
.esruoc fo aroruA dna ,elpuoc xof gnuoy a
,tsiaw ym dnuora dehcnub pu sdniw tnemrag eht erofeb selggig tfos emos dna ,sdrow-flah owt ro eno ,secnalg wef a egnahcxe ot evah I dna aroruA
.gof yvaeh-oot fo slirdnet gnizoo llits si eldnah leets sselniats a otni depmalc rab reppoc trohs a ,mih yb elbat eht nO
,skeehc ym fo htob fo lla nettog d’yehT
.evitnetta dna rednels ,eugnot a fo htmraw ehT
”.sseug I ,em tsuJ“ .gurhs I ,yllaniF
,hu ,neeb ev’dluoc ohw enoemos ekil dekool uoy ,naem I“
,ereh emac dna efil taht fo lla dnuownu I“ .rumrum I
.did I os dna ,dias eh ”,stun oG“
.dedracsid si dna seiromem skaewt koobraey A
.wonk t’nod I ,woN
.elttil a tsael ta ,thgirpu uoy teg s’teL“
.gnimoorg lufwa siht ,lesaew a rof kool doog a ton s’tI .yaw eht lla
.retaw fo puc lluf-flah eht gnidloh llits rehto eht
.neesnu thgiS .laeD“
,gurhs a htiw sthguoht gnicar ym edih I
liat ym dna roolf eht no dekcol seye ym htiw ,em dna
”.ffuts dna pu naelc pleh
,thguoht s’tnemom a retfA ”.uoy knaht
,yrd ot tfel nehw ylecin tcapmoc dnas fo sniarG
.eroc-drah noitisop ym kram ot ,esactius ym ni llits saw hcihw fo rettal eht
,em tsniaga pu sehsurb yteixnA
.syad emos ,rewols yaW“
.ecalp gnimoorg a morf emoS
.esiwrehto ti tup ot woh wonk yllaer t’nod I
.edis ym no tuo dial m’I
,knird I erom eht tub
”.hlgnmM“ .eb ot sah tI .aroruA
.em rof noitapucco na tsuj t’nsaw
,enituor emaceb ti neht tub
,ettal lausu reh perp ot edisni kcab ti ekam I nehW .liat reh fo
,ti devol nafetS
.deb eht no kcab yal ot em ediug ot thgiew reh fo stfihs eltbus dna swap reh gnisu
.ereh eb tsuj nac I tub ,yhw swonk ssendooG .ereh eb
em ot txen ni gnilttes erofeb ti no nwod em stis dna deb ym ot revo em sediug ehS
.swodniw enap-elgnis suolucidir esoht fo owt fo woble eht ni thgir tub rood eht morf tsehtraf
sraet htiw pu llew seye yM
.thgiarts naem I ,oN“
.si tsap eht erehw s’taht hguoht sa ,flesmih dniheb serutseg eH
,etoyoc eht ot kcab
.ecaf ym ot pu ti dloh dna rorrim a gans ot sehcaer tar ehT
.yawyna ,yaw taht em rof retteb ylbaborP
.espmilg a thguac I sseug I dna ,telbat a dah eH“
.dnim ym fo renroc a dnuora
,yrlewej elbisnes taht dna stiustnap trams eht otni thguob I
.gniddib s’etoyoc eht ta deb eht otno pu rehtruf toocs I ,llitS
.llew etiuq revo seog sihT
”,efil tsap“ ym ni retniap a neeb gnivah denoitnem I retfA
”.kcab elihw a devoM“ .psag I ”,haey…I“
.ti fo skool eht morf ,oot gniloorD
.weksa selbmut ,kcalb no ydnugrub
,madA htiw eciffo eht fo kcab tuo gnillihc ton m’I fI
,yhtlaew neeb reven dah I dna derraJ
.wap reh otno gnidloh peek I dna ,gnimoc peek sdrow sa—
”?tner ruoy nwod tuc ot od uoy nac tahW .kroW .eruS“
auqa elap a ot won dedaf—
.roloc rehtona rof deen on ,der dna kcalB
gniod…si siht yhw…yhw wonk t’noD“
.otlartnoc elbatrofmoc reh ni—sehciwdnas elpmis wef a evres ew—
gnittis neeb dah nafetS erehw rab eht fo dne eht dna egdirf klim eht neewteb degdew
.niaga dlrow taht fo trap a eb reve ll’uoy taht aedi eht fo og tel ot evah annog tsuj er’uoY
,tsacdop nwo reh no raeppa seirots reh fo ynaM
”.gnits ot gniog si sihT“
”.lla ta ecnatsbus oN
er’uoy…tsuj er’uoY .seY .naem I ,seY“
.spetstooF .laes a ta
.tnorf ym revo nwod erats dna ,kcals
.elihw a rof ereh evil nac I .kcuF
.atseis-hcnul-tsop eht dna secnuob-MA-enin eht dna seeffoc-erofeb ehT
ot evah t’ndid uoy ,aroruA sknahT“
.sesnecil sih lla no etad-ot-pu si dna ,thgirtuo ytreporp sih snwo eH .tes si madA
.yrrow t’nod ,uoy ta ssap a gnikam t’nia I“ ,shgual eH
.sleehw tnorf eht fo eno dniheb ylerauqs s’ti litnu kcik a ti evig I
,dda dna ,hguoht ,taht ta ti gnivael tsuj diputs leef I ”.sknahT“
.wons fo llems eht dna
.si ti tahw
.laretalloc on si hsac htiw melborP“
.roolf eht no yats yehT
.lla dna gniyrc morf em gnippotS .gnikroW
,ti dnuora
.egarag ruo fo ssem eht ni raeg gnikcapkcab dlo ym otni ylmrif dekcut somreht trauq-owt a sa desiugsid xob hsac gnikcol a ni
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.elttob akdov a fo tuo semoc tub ,citsatnaf s’mur ehT
,tser ot secalp gnidnif swaP
”.emoh uoy teg ll’I
,snigeb tar eht ”,tib tsrif
.revetahw ,nafetS dna madA htiw swap koohs I
.raet t’now esnecil ehT .efas eb tsum ti
,dnuora lrihw I dna eye ym sehctac retspmud eht tsniaga tsac swodahs eht ni noitoM
.kcab og ot gnivah fo ,derevocsid gnieb fo
tsartnoc eht dna
.sexaler ecaf ym tsniaga erusserp eht dna ,orez sehcaer nwodtnuoc ehT
.ecnelis elbatrofmoc A .ecnelis ni
”?erofeb dias I rebmun tahT
”ecnaraeppasiD“  saw sihT     .emit
”.nwotemoh ym was I“
.knup laer a otni nrut nac uoy os gnihtemos ro parc fo stros lla htiw decreip srae ruoy teG“
”.ma I ,haeY“ ”?yako uoY“
,swodahs ylno detniap I dna
,tsehc ym sllif yrc ot tuoba gnieb fo noitasnes tahT
”.sgnicreip emos deen tsuj uoy woN“
,selbat ytpme eht nwod gnipiw dna ngis ”nepo“ eht revo gnippilf semoc txeN
.keehc ym tsniaga sesserp gnihtemos sa niap neht dna ,rettalc a ,hsur A .gnirumruM
”.ycamitigel ruoy dniheb tfel uoy
.taht ekil yats I gnol woh wonk yllaer t’nod I
:epacsdnal taht gnirolpxe dna
.gnitniap m’I ,rehtie ton fI
.stros fo ”tneilc“ a sa ,éfac elttil s’nwot eht
,sdrac tpecca yehT .hsac ni yap I
”,nnn-N“ .tfil ot strats dna smra ym rednu pu swap reh spils ehS
,deen I fi fracs a htiw ti edih nac I
.srenroc eht ffo gnignah seitnap fo sriap owt dna
.neeb dah deb eht sa tsuj desopxe dna dedderhs si hcuoc ehT
.taht did I yhw wonk t’nod I
.ssik kciuq a reh evig ot pu nael dna niaga don I
;si ehs sa ,elbisnes s’tI
smra reh ta hctulc dna eganam I
.niaga yas I ”,kcuF“
.kciht ooT .htuom ym ni lluf oot sleef tI
.pmac pu tes neht dna ,si ti litnu rab eht ta ettal reh pis ll’ehs ,eerf t’nsi elbat reh fI
”?em tuoba ffo uoy deppit tahW“
”.mhmM“ .eson ym ta gnilkcit tnecs railimaf dna ruf
.siht fo lla retfa ssem a kool tsum I—
.evitisop reven s’ti tub ,ssecorp siht ,evitagen syawla ton s’tI
.noisseccus kciuq ni sneppah gnihtyreve ,neht morF
.edamemoh ylniatrec tsomla dna ,foorprevo yletinifed s’tI
.oot ,eyd eht teg llew sa thgim ;lla retfa ,sdnarb keehc eht tog I
.oot reh fo sllems rac ehT
,enola tfel yltsom si moorhtab ehT
uoy rof daer dna nettirw
,ssensselepoh erem otni noisserpxe ym gnicrof
,tnemtrapa eht dnuora elcric kciuq a ekam I
.tes lla siht dah I thguoht I yhw si hcihw ,srebmun htiw citsatnaf m’I
.sraj gninnac tnip-flah era sessalg ehT
.neve ,taht erofeB
?thgir ,efil ruoy htiw pu s’revetahw tuoba ssel gnikniht uoy tog I“
.knis eht ta ti sllif dna rab eht htaeneb morf
eman a fo tnih taht llits s’erehT .don I
.rettam ot smees ti ssel eht
seet dna strihs pu nottub deveels-trohs dna -gnol fo hcnub a dna ,triks savnac ysworf a ,snaej fo sriap eerht evah I
.tniap eht fo sseldeeh ,skeehc ym revo swap ym hsurb I
retteb hcum gnihtemos s’ereht tub
,smra s’etoyoc eht morf flesym gnilgnatnesid fo ,gnikool fo kniht I
.ffo em stuc ehs tub ,kaeps ot trats I ”.aroruA m’I
,dekcasnar si tesolc eht fo flehs pot ehT
.nageb noisrucxe elohw siht erofeb erots tfirht a morf debbarg I—llew tif hcihw fo emos ylno—
,kcalb ni eert lacirtemmys a dna neerg fo dnuorgkcaB
derugif I os ,lla retfa
,yletelpmoc kcab nworg tsomla sah ruf yM
.tniopyaw a tsuj s’ti ,taht naht rehtO
kcilf a htiw pohs eht fo tnorf eht ot renroc eht dnuor reh hctaw I sa gnihtaerb ym mlac ot gnilggurts
,llet dluoc I sa raf sa dna
.sdon ehs dna snetfos noisserpxe reh taht tA
,hguoht ,koot sub eht gnol woh dezilaer reven I
.sepahs fo saedi detalenerc
,llitS .haey ,retsaf tiB“
.gnitardyher no sucof I sa evird aroruA tel I ”.riaF“ .nirg I
,nosaer a rof yawa nworht
.rab eht no hcrep sih morf nwod spils nafetS ,gniddoN
.eciohc dooG .dooG“
,epag I ”?ohadI morf uoY“
,tekram eht drawot tuo kool dna tsif reh no keehc a tser ll’ehs semitemos tub ,seert eht ta skool tsuj ehs ,yltsoM
trofmoc ,won dnA .enola emit hcum oS
teliot eht esu I
.hgual ot nrut yM
”?senil thgiarts eht tnaw uoy erus uoY
”.ssem a fo tib a era uoY“
.daetsni em ssik ot ni snael
.sgnipeews ruf sdne-dna-sddo fo gab a barg dna rac eht ni hcaer I
.eerf tsud ,sevlehs no s’ffutS
”.wonk ot tnaw llits t’nod I naem t’nseoD .esop’s I“
.em dleh ehs nehw ekil sllems tI
,efil ni saw eh erehw htiw tnetnoc dna nekops-tfos sa ffo emac eH
,em tsniaga klub mraw a si aroruA
etiuq ton hguoht ,srae ym drawot pu dna enilwaj eht ot nwod
elbmut nevenu ,neddus a dna
dehcuot t’nevah I
.sreh ot eson ym sserp ot daeh ym tlit I
.kcab ylizoc detnac srae eninac gnol reh
.boj a teg t’nac tsuj I tuB
.etihw ni emoc ot gnitrats er’yehT
.knalb seog dnim yM
.elggig I ,hguoht ,skcilc ti ecnO
uoy rof daer ,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,thgirlA“ .tnereffiD
.ffuts ytreporp seod madA elihw tuo dna ni dekcehc sklof gnitteg trats dna s’madA ot kcab hsad ot owt ro ytriht eno yb tuo daeh I
.somreht ym otni yaw sti gnikam hsac artxe taht lla
.taorht ym ni hctac sdrow yM ”—ym was I“
.rab eht
.ti tuoba yrrow ot gnidih ysub oot neeb d’I neht ecnis dna
”.edisni uoy teg s’teL“ .elims taht
.ylluferac tsom nekorb si kcolc A
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.cinap fo esnes krad eht ffo ekahs ot
.sisrahtac eht rof ti yortsed ot ylno gnippots
,ruf hguorht swalc ym ecart d’I
,gnissarrabme etiuq yllautca s’thguoht ehT
tsixe yllagel t’nseod lesaew taht fi srebmun nur ot lesaew tsetrams eht neve erih ot gniog si eno oN
.rac eht fo tnorf eht dnuora ylkciuq sedirts dna taes reh fo tuo flesreh srevel aroruA
,elpmis a flesym wolla yllanif I
”,kool doog a ton ylbaborp ,haeY“
,taes eht otni hcuols dna yaw eht fo tuo triks dna liat ym epiws I nehT
”.mM“ ”.elihw a rof ereh tuo evil ot hguone gnola thguorb I .on ,lleW“ .syas eh
.eyd fo ebut a gniyub otni em deklat neht
dnuora eotpit ot elba neeb ylno ev’I taht nihtiw diov ytpme taht tsael ta ro—
,emoH“ .swap sih no kcab snael dna snirg flow ehT
.kcen ym ot tnorf ym revo pu gnilruc lirdnet rehtona dna
.snoitatcepxe on htiw ecnelis A .ecnelis tneitap ,dnik A
.detcepxe sa ysae sa si hsac htiw seirecorg gnitteG
.daetsni sredluohs ym dnuora smra reh spils dna gniggut ym otni sevig neht ,nwod kcab selttes dna stneler ehS .flesym lortnoc ot htaed gnidnepmi fo esnes a yb kcurts oot
ro ffo meht gninrut
”?ees uoy d’tahW .rebmemer I ,haey
.rethgil eht fo mir eht evoba gnikeep ylerab ylno
dnoces gnilbmuf rehtona sekat ti os ,reh fo og tel ot htaol m’I
.ssenhsiffodnats sa yek ym revo gnidnah elihw ecnelis sih nekat d’I
.don I ”?huh ,elihw a neeB“
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.tnorf ym tsniaga ylluf erom stser ehs sa sedis ym gnola hsurb ot sredluohs ym yb morf swap reh gnignirb
”.em ot evitnatsbus leef uoY“
,seiradnuob dna segde gnibircsed cra htooms a si eno hcae
,krow dluow ti ekil tlef tI .ot detnaw I“
”.siht ekil gnihton tsuj tub
,ni pu dnuow I nwot elttil siht ot kcits I ,daetsnI
gnihtynA .detrats ruf dednarb ,etihw eht dna
.gniyrc fo tros mlac tsomla ,eltneg a otni elttes dna ,sbos fo tuo nur I ,yllautnevE
.taorht s’eno ffo sesolc dna tug s’eno otni selttes taht ssenkcis gnizinoga taht otnI .rorret otnI
,eciov ym krow ot woh tuo erugif t’nac I ”.uoy fo tnorf ni sgel ruoy teg tsael ta
.haey ,sseug I“ .sgurhs neht
.ylper a htiw pu emoc t’nac I ”?etoyoc ehT“
”.em gnivird rof niaga sknahT“ .don I
”.ssenisub ym toN
.meht dnuora ecaps hcum os evah semoh dna serots yhcstik eseht fo ynam os ecnis ,si ti naht reggib skool tI
.ot gnikil a nekat ev’I taht evots tekcor a dna swodniw enap-elgnis eguh htiw éfac elttil taen a s’erehT
.raj ym otni
.ereht gnitteg m’I tuB .tey toN
taerht tnatsnoc rednu saw hcihw tub
.wodniw eht tuo gnirats
.revo ti pit tsuj I
.deworrob ylno em-tsap emit ot pu dda lla yeht ,esle gnihtyna
nwodtnuoc hcae neewteb htaerb rof gnipsag neewteb gnitanretla ruoh flah txen eht dneps I
.nirg yfoog a skcarc neht ,regnol elttil a stiaw tar ehT
.skeehc ym no sdnarb gnilaeh eht ta sgut elims A ”?thgiartS“
”.t’nod I“ ”?wonk t’nod uoY“
”ecnaraeppasiD“   yojne esaelP
.thgiN yrratS ta moorhtab eht ni gnikcinap
.rac ym ot tnaem I“
.sredluohs ym no swap reh stser dna daeh reh sekahs ehS .kaorc I ”,yrroS“
.t’nseod tahw dna skrow tahw sserpxe ot stfihs eltbus dna snaom teiuQ
.siht od ot elba eb tsuj thgim I ,tner no gnitteg m’I laed eht htiw tub
.ekaw sih ni gof gniknis a gniwollib swap dalc-ttim-nevo ni guj-flah eht
.nac I tseb sa sdrow rof tnuh I
.sniamer sti ot em deit taht lla deyortsed dna
.retaw eht ta pis dna don I
.stsirw reh dnuora dehcnub htolc trihs-t htiw ruf ym ni deirub era swalc dna sregnif reH
”.meht tuohtiw eb d’I tahw tuoba gnikniht dna