.daer-pil ot tpmetta reh fo tuo esnes on gnikam dna htuom rieht no daetsni gnisucof
oot sraef ruoy neht ,flesruoy fo raef eht rof sdnuorg on si ereht fi
.nirg eninac a ni nepo-flah htuom sti dnuof dna
tnaem wenk enoyreve hcihw ,ylnO nosreP nI
.dezingocer tsomla ehs epahs a saw ti dnA
,pu dekool ehs nehw dna ,tnemevom eht ta nwod kcab decnalg ehS
,reprahs emaceb ezeerb ehT
.tnerruc eht gnileef dellac nwot ni slleps dlos ohw sdraziw eht tahw ebyam
.mra rehto rieht tuo gnidloh won saw ohw ,tsohg eht ta pu kcab decnalg ehS
,diarb reicnaf a dah srieht :meht erapmoc ot s'tsohg eht ediseb mra reh dleh ehS
.mrahc ruf a llits yletinifed saw ti tub
kcab evoorg gnitirw rieht gnitteg s’ohw
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,tnecs dnoces eht dellac aM tahw
gniht lufraef a si tI
.dewollA sevlowereW oN
,rellud srewolf-hctid fo tnecs eht
.dnah reh no seye rieht dexif dna
.dniw eht otni ti gnippans dna gur gar dlo s’amaM pu gnikcip denigami dna
.luferac eb ot truh reven ti tub
,emit a ta yrots trohs eno
,reh thguat dah narG yaw eht flesreh gnirehtag dna dlrow eht tuo gnittuhs
erifpmac fo remmilg a was ehs
.tseW no meht dnes ot dedeen d’yeht tahw saw ereh tuo nik detcepxenu gnidnif fi ro
,ekahsdnah a etiuq ton
niaga seye reh desolc treB
ebyam–dnah a tuo dleh yehT
.hcaer fo tuo tsuj
.kcen s'treB fo kcab eht delkcirp ezeerb gnineve ehT
:brevorp rehtona spahrep ro
,detniop d’ehs noitcerid eht nI
",daor eht no efas uoy peek oT"
,ztaK xelA yb ”snisuoC tnatsiD“
,srenroc eht ni ssarg llat eht tuoba gnitrad sgub gninthgil eht gnoma nrettap on ,gnihton was ehS
delebal neeb lla dah sessalc cigam eht
remraw saw thgin eht
.daD regdaB yldduC a ,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,ztaK xelA yb ”snisuoC tnatsiD“ saw sihT
.ffuc trihs reh fo tuo nellaf dah taht ruf dediarb fo telecarb eht was ehs
.enog saw tsohg eht
.no ruf htiw od ot reisae saw ti dnA
,ylsuoituac dehcaorppa ehS
,seye reh desolc dna dessorc sdaor eht erehw morf secap wef a deppots ehS
.thginot siht ekil yrots a raeh ot dedeen ohw enoemos saw ti
.erif taht tliub d’ohw ees dna daor eht pu daeh tub od ot tfel gnihton saw ereht dna
.sdaorssorc eht ta gnihtemos saw erehT
,eltsihw tnatsid a gniraeh fi sa detlit daeh ,desuap yehT
uoy dnif ll'ti ,enim dna ruf s'am ruoY" .erofeb syad erem tsirw s'treB dnuora ti deit d'ehs sa dias dah amaM
,seye reh denepo ehs nehW
".og uoy erehw rettam on snisuoc ruoy
.hguone doog saw tahT
,ti ta nwod gnikooL
,ykcul saw ehs fI
.reh nefaed ot denetaerht ti litnu gnillews surohc tekcirc eht
,ezeerb eht no deregnil meht fo gnihtemos fi gnillet oN
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
?llew sa deraef era hcihw sgniht yb deraef eb ot
.goD fo tsohG ehT
.eye eht ni daed reh dekool dna daeh rieht denrut tsohg eht tnemom eht ta htaerb reh gnidloh saw ehs dezilaer ehS
,dluoc ehs sa kciuq sa ezag reh deppord ehS
,dehcterts ssenllits ehT
:raef tsap kool ot eno hcaet nac deraef gnieb tuB
.nialpxe ot deirt ehs nehw dootsrednu yllaer reve dah narG tub eno on taht
.uoy hguorht thgir hcaer dluoc ohw enoemos rof hguone esolc tub
.golb gnidliubdlrow rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.ydob rehto reh ni deciton ylerab d’ehs sdnuos dna sllems fo lluf ezeerb eht dna
,reh ees dluoc yeht eetnaraug on saw erehT
,llih txen eht revo ekoms erifpmac sa dedaf dna tniaf sa
.stekcirc fo surohc eht htaeneb senigne ro spetstoof fo dnuos on draeh
.ria eht ni gnihtemos yletinifed saw ereht tuB
.sreh ekil yrev telecarb a erow yeht ,tsirw taht nO
.meht retfa derepsihw ehs ”,nisuoc ,sknahT“
ti si lufraef erom hcum woh neht ,os si ti fi dnA .deraef eb ot
?meht htiw hctih ot reh gnitivni
ztaK xelA yb ”snisuoC tnatsiD“
:tcaf ni era yeht taht revocsid tey yam sgniht lufraef dnA .flesti raef si
,sdaorssorc eht fo elddim eht ni flowerew rehtonA
,niaga devom telecarb eht htiw dnah ehT
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.nehctik s’amaM ni gur gar eht ekil rehtegot sevlesmeht gnittonk gnieb reh fo srebif yrev eht gninigami
,tfig fo tros a dah syawla d'ehS
.revo llup reven dluow taht tfil a rof niav ni gnibmuht
.daor eht fo hcnarb rehtona nwod detniop dna daeh reh koohs ehS
.snoitpo reh deredisnoc dna daor eht fo elddim eht morf kcab deppets ehs sa rethgil hcuot a tlef luos nwo reh ,sseldrageR
,golatac esruoc ecnednopserroc MNU eht ni :sdraziw fo elttil wenk ehS
?og noitidart taht did kcab raf woH
,larom A .sseldnuorg eb yam
,ecaf s'tsohg eht ta pu kcab dekool ehS
raef ot evah ew gniht ylno eht
,mlap denrutpu reh evoba gnitser
,won regnorts saw ezeerb eht ni epahs ehT
.sevlowerew ot dneirf on erew ereht elpoep eht fi nevE
.ereht yllaer erew taht sgniht eht gniees ti llac ot derreferp ehS
.derednow ehs ,deid yeht dah oga gnol woH
:brevorp dlO  .daD regdaB yldduC a
tnecs dna thgis fo noitanibmoc emos ni
,raet dna raew erom tib a dna
.mrah on tnaem ehs wohs ot tuo sdnah