semuser eludehcs raluger ruO
.htnoM yrteoP sedulcnoc sihT
,nosnogarD .T xelA yb
.remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer
,relevart wollef ruoy floWcaM boR si sihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
?terger on htiw ,dluoc dna
nruter dluow I erows dna
,neeserof evah I dluoC
.lla ta emit on tey dnA
hcuoc railimaf ym morf tuo kool I sA
,devol I gnihtyreve morF
.golb gnidliubdlrow rieht no dna
,”yrotciV elbaifitnauQ ,tnatsiD“   yojne esaelP
,flesym ksa I nwotemoh erutuf
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
yawa secnanif ym wolloF ot thgilf lufetaf
ecalp siht ot gnimoc ni gnol os neeb evah I
,nwonk evah I dluoC nalp a dah I
,nruter dluow I taht
denigami evah I dluoc
evihcra goD fo ecioV eht ni seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.remrahC eniuqE eht
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
,gab ym dah I erofeb dnA
”yrotciV elbaifitnauQ ,tnatsiD“ saw sihT
txet s'etammaet a morf tuo dnuof dna
oga shtnom thgie
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
em detxet rehtom ym nehw ,oga skeew xiS
,emoh-yllaer-ton gnimoc ,esactius ym rof gnitiaw saw I elihW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw ro god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ,seirots erom htiw ,keew txen fo sa
taht dedraob I nehW oga sraey owt
nosnogarD .T xelA yb meop a
kcab og ot nalp a dah I fi
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
regnol on boj ym saw ti taht
boj ym ta ni gol ot deirt dna deirt I nehW
,emit a ta hpargarap eno ni evil ot tnaw yeht dlrow eht gnidliub si ohw
dna ecno ym ni ,seert wen ta
,wodniw wen a hguorhT
,nosnogarD .T xelA yb