.etamitni…erom elttil a tlef ereh ni gnidnirg
.dnuora nrut neve t’ndid elgaeb dlo eht
sdnah sih thguorb nairB sa tocsam tcudorp gninaelc a fo
.taht detseggus I sa
,dlob erom elttil a tog I nehT
”.ereh em gnignirb erofeb taht fo thguoht ev’dluohs...llew
,niaga deksa rotaderp eht
.moor ym dehcaer ew ecno neppah ot gniog saw tahw ybsressap ot raelc yrev ti edam eH
.taerter ym dekcolb emarf-deb ym litnu
”.yllautneve kcab emoc annog s’eH“
”.dekcolnu siht tfel I nrows
,oot ,daetsni rehtegot stnorf ruo gnihsurc erew eW
”!neht ti ot teg retteb ew neht lleW“
.eciwt dehsad drac-V diputs siht fo dir teg dna
.dehctiwt ti sa taeb a deppiks traeh ym
.yawllah eht fo tser eht yb deipuccoerp oot erew sthguoht ym tub ,ecnetnes sih fo trats eht draeh I
tub ni llats rehto taht ni sdnuos suodnerroh eht tuoba liated erom otni og d’I
.hguoht ,staews sih rednu meht gnittup dna
.hguorht wollof ot em gnitcepxe saw eh kniht t’nod I
,rood ruoy no kcos eht was ew ,hO“
.rood ym ta deppots ew sa
?!ereh eh saw lleh eht yhw tuB
pu kcehc tuo dna ni kciuq a neeb ev’dluow ti thguoht ew sa tsuJ
.llats eht edisni kcehc ot kniht t’ndid ohw .A.R eht yb llats eht ffo deggard gnieb won
detidE si yrots sihT
.llaw mrod eht tsniaga em demmals neht dna
”,pu tuhS“  .derepmihw I
.won pu evig t’nac ew ,nam ,no emoc dna
.snoitcaretni etamitni etavirp rof ecalp tseb eht t’nera smrod egelloc
,niaga mih ta dekool I
.tekcop kcab sih ni ti deffuts eh erofeb ylesolc oot ti ta kool t’ndid eh esoppus I ”.og ew erehT“
.evaeh a dna hcuorc a neht
,niorg erab ym gnippirg saw dnah elohw eht
,nosrep suorutnevda na ton m’I
,flesmih ot delbmurg ithA
denediw slipup dettils sih raews I
Y“  .erusopmoc ym gniniager erofeb naom rehtona htiw dednopser I
!etaN etammoor ym s’taht dna ho-
.mih rof pirts ot gniog llits saw I hguohtlA
.sselecirp saw ecaf sih no kcohs ehT
tcaer ot hguone rebos neve emos
ot gnittimmoc eb dluohs I taht gnihtemoS
.kcab emac nirg yrotaderp sih
,tfel eh ,tuo deleehw gnieb tnempiuqe fo tekcub dna eltsihw a htiW
eno siht piks nac uoy
pu thguac os erew eW
,detrats eh sa em morf flesmih evomer ot gnirehtob ton
,deksa rotpar ehT
”.em eveileb t’nod uoy fi rood modnar a tsniaga rae ruoy tuP
.nirg a otni gnipahs htuom sih fo renroc eht no hteet fo remmilg thgils eht was I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,nataC yalp annog er’eW“
,erom tib elttil taht tsuj meh sih gnirewol
,tergraM ,kcirreD ,aliM ,yrreJ ,wonk uoy ,haeY“
”…ti tuoba gnikniht ,yug rehtona otni og eno nees reven ev’I
,em dennip eh sa tniat ym gnilkcit dna sllab ym gnigassam
saw I sa hcum sa tib yreve ti gniyojne saw nairB erus m’I
”.lliw yeht erus m’I“
.ti morf ecnedifnoc fo gnap thgils a tog I
,tuo dnah sih dehcaer eH
,delaever saw emarf ralucsum siH
”?edisni teg uoy nehw gnippirts trats uoy t’ndluohS“
.delwoy yletaidemmi I dna ,taht ekil tsuj
,ti wenk I erofeB
,timda ll’I  ---  .em ta dereel dna
.suovren tib a saw I
.won thgir gniht taht
mih rof ni gnittes cinap eht saw ti fi wonk t’nod I
”?eunitnoc annaw ,os ,yakO“
.nwod yaw eht lla meht gnikat
,rood eht morf emac ”!nam ym ,etaN !oooY“
.uoy ekil eno etuc a ton
,dednuofbmud ot dehctiws nairB no ecaf yrotaderp taht won yB
.yruxul yldrah saw ti hguoht ,rehtegot llats a ypucco su ees ot dnuora saw eno on ,yllufknahT
,walc sih no dekooh raewrednu dedracsid ym dah eh taht tcaf eht yb dezisahpme
.won sehtolc deen t’nod I tub
---  .ffo tnew srelknirps s'moor eht nehT
”.ssalc 053 YSP ym …ym morf nairB
,tlef ti sa gib sa dekool gniht nmad ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
gniht elbanosaer eht did ew ,yllarutan oS
:yojne esaelP   terreFekuD dna
…llats ruo hcaorppa spetstoof reh draeh ew
.roolf moor erots eht no denaorg ylsuoenatlumis eW
.dial gnitteg tuohtiw ti tfel ev’dluow tsomla I dna
”?012 yhposolihP“
walc sih no gnignah llits raewrednu ym
repeed tog eh I tsurht yreve htiW
.llats eht evoba daeh sih ekop ot ton sa os
,ereht fo tuo ti deliathgih I dna nairB sselehtenoN
,ecarg enivid emos yb dna
”.ERIF FO ESAC NI KAERB“
.nwod dekcid tog I elihw moor eht ni eb ot gnilliw yltnerappa lla
‐‒nuf ruo eunitnoc yllanif dluoc ew ebyam dna
”!detaert teg ot nrut ruoy s'tI
,gnihtolc fo meti emos dah rood rehto yreve tsomla ekil demees ti
.rehtegot shgiht ym dnirg em ekam ot hguone llits tub ffits elttil a
,retsum dluoc I htgnerts eht lla htiw os ,taht gnivah t’nsaw I
.niaga ecno hctorc ym tsniaga nethgit stnap ym tlef I dna kcab emac eciov tnedifnoc dna yrtlus eht
doow sevlehs eht otni gud swalc yM
.lairetam eht fo gniknilc eht pots ot gnihton od dluoc I sa tleb ym no neht
”.etaN uoy htiw m’I ,thgirlA“
.tnasaelpnu gnihtyna tuo nword dluoc taht ainomma fo ffihw tniaf a su gnivig
.ecnalab esol ot nairB gnisuac llaw eht ffo dehsup I
,peY .dab os t’nsaw llats depmarc eht woN
.gnikcuf erew uoy elihw edih ot emit dedeen dneirfyob ruoy dna uoy esac ni
lleW‘ ,dias dna ,ereh kcab emoc ot dediced ew oS“
,regral hcum tub enim sa prahs sa ,hteet s’nairB
,cassI“  ”.esneffo
.ni gniggid saw eh raf woh htiw
ecaf sih ot dnah ym thguorb I
.detaefed…dednuos eH ”.etaN ,yrros m’I“
yrrebnikceH sucraM sretirw wollef yb
worromot dne annog si retsemes siht kniht oT
.won nwod gnuh daeh sih dah rotpar ehT
”?siht tnaw ’nikcuf yllaer uoY“
,sisordysP   yb ”brutsiD ton oD“
.taht fo hguone dah htob ew kniht I
”!lla retfa thginot emos teg ot degannam uoy ,edud haey kcuF
,senidras ekil rehtegot desserp erew ew
.rehto hcae gnildnof su detpurretni etammoor ym retfa deppots ev’dluow syug tsom ekil leef I
tub pleh t’ndluoc I
eglub elbatrofmocnu na htiw mih dna
.em ta kool ot revo kcab ti thguorb dna
?thgir ,tesolc siht ni sevlesruo ot emit fo tnuoma doog a evah d’ew dna
,dloheb dna wol ,esuaceb dezilaromed saw eh dna dekan saw I won ,lleW
?mih gnidael eno eht eb I dluoc woH
redluohs ym no dnah a tup eH
.strohs rexob sih fo tuo thgir sullahp eht gnillup
,em ffo llaf retaews sih tel I
.rood llats eht no stnap ym gnah ot elba yllanif saw I erofeb semit wef a tsael ta sdaeh dettub ew
.dehcaorppa eh sa ecaf ym revo poord riah tpmeknu ym leef dluoc I
.ssa ym tsniaga gnileef saw I tahw sseug
.dnim ym dessorc evah thgim taht taerter fo aedi yna pots ot hguone saw tahT
;em otno flesmih hsup yllaunam ot evah t’ndid eh woN
.ciffart ni ffo tuc gnieb tuoba dam teg ot drawkwa oot enoemos ekil gniklat saw eH
,naem I ,emit rehto emos niaga pu teem ew t’nod yhw ,mu ,yeH“
yllautneve htuom ym nepo ot dah I
fi sa krad eht ni mih dniheb deporg dnah sih ,oN
.thguac tog tsomla ew emit driht eht yb dereggirt hgih nihprodne na no tfel htob erew ew dna
”?gniog ew era erehW“
,spil ym dekcil ylrignuh
stnap fo riap eno sunim eM
.dluoc I yrros m’I sseldrow
tekcaj eht fo mottob eht detrap  I
.noitca koot nairB tub esle enoemos yb dehcuot gnieb em fo ksir eht ro
,ti ekil t’nod uoy fi
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.hsur eht ni tleb ym nettogrof d’I ecnis ,emit tsal sa thgit sa ton hguohT
.kcohs ni kcab dereep dna
.dedeen I tahw teg ot hguone tsuj rewol ot  em rof hguone ysae erew staews sih
.gnikool tuohtiw dedeen eh tahw ekat ot moor siht htiw hguone railimaf
.sesucxe eseht ffo gnitsil tpek eh sa rehto hcae ta derats I dna nairB
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,llew…repap teliot dedeen eh fi tub
.dluoc uoy nehw rehtegot shgiht ym dnirg em gnikam gnikcuf erew uoY“
hcum os pu dnats ruf ym edam ti...slworg sih fo dnuos eht
retal meti dnuof dna tsol railucep a tuoba liame ediw roolf a teg d’eW
,selkna ym dnuora erew enim ecnO
,hhu ,tiaW“   --eht gnuh tsuj I
a…eciwt detpurretni neeb ev’ew tub skcus ti wonk I ?mH“
!selohssa esoht fo yna naht erom dekcuf teg ot devresed I ,tinmaddoG
.ereh ni teg dluoc ew sa depmarc sa tuoba erew ew
.kcoc tcere llits ym mih tneserp ot
.delbmurg etammoor detairbeni ym
fi flesym ot ecalp eht evah d’I dias eH
”?oot ,sruoy esu ro ,ti htiw gniyalp peek ot gniog uoy era ,lleW“
.dnuora nrut ot em dlot eh nehT
,detcartsid tog nairB
,drocca nwo ym no stnap sih rof tnew I os
.niaga eciov sih ni saw lworg thgils ehT
”.sknaht ,ssap ll’eW“
.deddon dna pil mottob ym tib tsuj I
?erus uoY“  ”.tuo
,selkna ym dnuora loop tnemrag eht gnittel
.ereh yaw rieht gnikam stneduts suoiruc fo sdnuos eht tuo nword ot hguone duoL
,nwo ym naht rehto ,erofeb kcid a dehcuot reven d’ohw enoemos sA
”?won thgir kcuf ew t’nod yhw neht ,lleW“
enoemos saw nairB
,won thgir rettam t’ndid taht tub niaga ssenkrad ni tfel htob erew eW
!hu huN“  .tsirw ym psalc dnah a tlef I neht tuB
daeh…ot gniog yllautca er’ew ,mU“
.fles edun ym revo retaews sih epard ot hguone ecin saw ,egnar srelknirps eht fo tuo yats ot deganam ohw
.llew eno siht gnildnah saw I wonk ot ecin saw ti
.ffo gniwohs tsuj s’taht ,roolf s’yob a
,noitcere ym rof tnew dnah rehto sih sa gnihton dias eH
.elims deifirret ylthgils ,adnik osla tub eniuneg ylthgils a no gnittup elihw gnirewoc
,regnol tib a tsuj deunitnoc eh fI
noos esuaceb llet dluoc I
,mih ta dekool yldrawkwa I
hguohtla …kcid a nees lla ev’eW
esuac‘ ,foorpdnuos saw tesolc siht taht depoh I .ti tsol I nehw saw liat ym rednu elzzum sih gud eh tnemom eht ,kcuF ?em emalb uoy dluoc ,taht od enoyna tlef ev’I emit tsrif eht saw siht ,nam ,kcuf tub
,decnemmoc gnilffuhs drawkwa eroM
.mih dniheb rood eht desolc rotpar eht sa ecaf ym no gnillaf ylraen
.diarfa yllautca t’nsaw I wenk eh epoh I
.slipup eulb ynihs dna seye wolley thgirb sih gnieb erutaef elbisiv ylno sih gnivael
.yawa ytinigriv ym kcuf dna moor ym ot kcab emoc ot mih ecnivnoc ot deganam neve I
.derettum yldeyonna A.R ehT
,god.ecioveht ta
tsehc ym fo tuo gnidnuop yllacitcarp saw traeh yM
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”,kciuq siht ekam dluohs eW“
.thguoht dnoces a tuohtiw ti dehctans ithA dna
?eugnot elitper a tlef reve uoy
,htaehs ym morf eerf gnignah kcoc ym ees ydaerla dluoc I
sdnah ym gnikat morf mih pots t’ndid tahT
.maets gnittime ylbisiv eb d’I kniht I
.rednulb tsrif ruo retfa tfel ew erehw
.gnippird ydaerla saw em fo edis eno ,lleW
”,elbirret taht llems t'nseod ti tsael tA“
”…dna etal gnitteg s'ti
yot yob rotpar sih dna netram enip sselmottob a gniees morf teef owt tuoba llits saw eh tub
.ti gniniur s’eh won dna thginot ’emos teg‘ ot em degaruocne ohw flow emas eht saw sihT .dednamed I
,niaga nepo gnulf srood moorhtab ehT
”.yppas teg t’nod ,hO“
ev’dluoc I“  .ti fo dnoces yreve evol annog saw I timmad dog dna ,tesolc s’rotinaj a ni ytinigriv ym esol yllaiciffo ot tuoba saw I
,em htiw elssah on os ,tleb oN
denruhc hcamots ym sa desaercni gnidnuop-traeh ym ,niagA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.hguoht ,noitcere sih nessel ot gnihton did
dna dnoces a ni derusaelp ot gnitadimitni morf tnew ecaf siH
”,ebab ,mih rof hguone eb lliw sdnuos ehT“
.duol I saw kcuf yloH
”?elttil a kcab evom ,hu uoy nac ,yeH“
.em rof llaf ot detcepxe reven I
‒ecaf sih ffo ton llits cinap
wodahs ni dekab ecaf sih
,nwod gnikooL
”?sgar ym era erehw ,hgU“
.esirprus ni epaga won saw
.tesolc moorb nmad a otni em wollof ot ssengnilliw sih did os tub ,yawa ti evag yllaer sdnah gnikahs ehT
nwo sih deronoh ev’dluow eh thguoht I !yrros os ma I“
,kcab ym tsniaga tsiaw sih desserp eh ,did I sA
naht mraw em gnipeek ta boj retteb a od dluow ruf erab ym dna dekaos saw gniht nmad eht
.raewrednu dna trihs ym tsuj ni
.nialpmoc ot tuoba t’nsaw I tub
em fo og tel nairB sa noos sa esuac
emit yreve tub yllanoisacco meht ot kcab gnikool
.moor sih ot kcab nemhserf elttil yknid a
,edud ,taerg eb dluohs emit tsrif ruoY“
”.ebab ,em rof dnuora nruT“
.stnap sih otni kcab ffuts ot gniyrt saw eh
,pu tliub reve ev’I erp tsom eht ylbaborp s’tahT
.eldnah eht no skcos ym decalp ylsuolucitem I sa
?ees eh did tahW
.gnol rof roolf eht no yats enim fo gnihtyna tel ot gniog t’nsaw I ,dellems ecalp siht naelc woh rettam on
”,siht eunitnoc nac ew erehw secalp fo ytnelp era ereht ,yrrow t’noD“
,ni degnulp ti daetsnI
,duht a htiw ssarg eht no dednal eH
H“  .oot eciwt ro ecno mih dessik I
,enim sa gnorts sa t’nsaw sih fo eson rotpar tahT
.mih edir ot detrats dna
sesiri eulb lacitrev s’rotaderp eht no dekcol llits saw noitnetta ym hguohtlA
”?huh ,gniyonna elttil a gnitteg si sihT“
,wenk ydaerla I ,hcihw ;em dniheb rood eht dna em neewteb gnicnalg saw eH
nwod gnihcuorc ,taes teliot desolc eht fo pot no debmilc dna smra ym yb pu em detsioh eh ,tnatsni na nI
.kaerb revo sroolf eht gninihs eb d’ew moor ylppus sih ni gnikcuf su thguac eh fi tub ,lla dna elgaeb looc a saw ithA ,woN
dekrims dna renob ym
,delworg rotpar eht ”?ew erew erehW“
noitnetta sih teg ot ti tsniaga dnuorg dna ytinutroppo eht koot I oS
.flehs eht tsniaga ,ylbatrofmocnu ylthgils
retsemes siht dial teg ot ecnahc tsal ym saw sihT
,seenk ym tsap deppils yeht retfa og tel eH
.moorhtab eht edistuo morf draeh ew ”!.A.R“
”,gib taht ton s'ti wonk I haey-
.dekcuf htob er’ew neht
.em sa etarepsed sa tib yreve saw eh taht dewohs
won‒sregnif owt tegroF  ”?ew era ,regaE“
.uoy erutcnup yllacitcarp dluoc ti
.ygolopa eht dnatsrednu t’ndid yleniuneg I
.trofmoc rof meht fo tuo deppets I
sdaer taht lenap egral etiuq llits tub ,elbisiv ylerab a otno
,sruo morf tnecajda llats eht ot gnidaeh spetstoof reivaeh emit siht
pot knat a rednu depparw
.selacs sih fo neerg peed eht tsniaga
,niaga derettum eH
,seye s’nairB ni raef fo tnih thgils a was I yas tsomla d’I
noitnetta sih tog yletinifed tahT
.si ecalp siht elbatrofmocnu woh dezilaer eh retfa oot mih rof ffo erow ycaidemmi yxes eht gnisseug m’I ,hguohtlA
s’tahT .kcuf yloh-
,emit tsrif eht rof fles dekan yletelpmoc ym fo lufeye na mih gnivig
,ti ni kcid emos teg ot nepo dleh ylremrof ,waj ym dna deppord traeh yM
.thginot dekcuf teg dna tuo og ot ecivda eht em nevig d’ohw flow eht saw tI
.em ni kcid sih tup neve d’eh erofeb gnippird eb d’I pu siht tpek eh fI
.gnidliub eht fo tuo gnikcud ssa sselmottob ym fo dniw thguac enoyna erofeb roodkcab eht tuo em rehsu ot deganam eh
”.uoy fo tser eht sa etuc sa llits s'tI“ .dekcom eh
,thginot emit tsrif eht rof sgnaf ym derab I sa
”-dna ni emac tsuj eh tub ecivda nmaddog
,ssenkrad ni su gnipeek
.selacs fo aes sih ssorca decnad sregnif ym sa em gnillik saw noitapicitna ehT
,ees ot meht fo lla rof ydob dekan ym erab ll’I
seye esoht rednu tub
O“ .etarepucer dluoc eh erofeb kcid sih otno flesym dengilaer I
,sthgiewthgil etah I“  .sgel ym
.raewrednu ym ni demrofrep I hceeps a htiw mih gnitavitom boj dab a od t’ndiD
,dereviuq I ”,skcos ym tsuJ“
,nepo gnuws ti sa rood tesolc eht dniheb denoitisop yltneinevnoc
esuac‘ ,won kcirt tah ’nikcuf a saw tI
!gnikcuf si esle enoyrevE
;ekatsim a saw tahT
,netram enip detrevortni na tsuj m’I .llew…thginot tub
,sevlehs eht gninil stcudorp gninaelc suoirav eht htiw
,ffo eno leep ot toof eno no gnidnats
mrod ruo fo tnorf eht edistuo skcurt erif eht dna saremac morf thgil fo sehsalf ehT
,si sa detcejed tleF
.em hctid ot nairB rof hguone doom eht niur t'ndid cassI dalg tsael ta saw I ”!etaN no emoc
.sriats fo sthgilf eerht pu gniog citamhtsa na ekil gniffuh t'nsaw eh dna hctib a ekil gninaom ton I saw emit elgnis a toN
.niaga ni devohs saw I dnA
.em dniheb eilacs eht ot sknaht lla saw ti dna
.gel ym pu detfil I sa sredluohs ym no thgit gnippirg sdnah dewalc
,eurt s’taht dnA ”…riaF“
,gnirueyov eno eht naht rehtar
,wonk uoy ,deriuqer saw gninraw ehT ”!ni gnimoC“
,trihs a saw tfel dah I gnihtolc fo elcitra ylno eht taht ni knas ti kniht t’nod I
.mrala eht fo thgil etihw gnidnilb lanoisacco eht htiw nosinu ni deralb sneriS
.flesmih ot ylno deklat tub ,rentrap ym ta detniop eH ”…ym
ecaf gnilims eht ta gnirats
.sdneirf rieht fo krow eht evorpmi ot ecneirepxe gnitide sih sesu dna
.tesolc eht morf seilppus gnirehtag
.deohce stneduts egelloc knurd deyonna fo stuohs derruls dna srumrum eht erehw gnidliub eht fo tnorf eht drawot dekool eH  .dednammoc I
.tcere sa llits ,reilrae morf rebmem suoirolg taht tuo gnippolf dna stnap sih gnirewol ,deksa eh
.syek sih htiw delbmuf eh sa htaerb sih rednu rettum rotinaj mrod eht fo eciov s’rekoms ylworg eht raeh ot dah ew
.tnedicni eldoon yttihs siht tuohguorht lla em htiw kcits did eh
.tesnus eht otni yobwoc a ekil kcid a edir ot tuoba saw I
,meht deen t’nod I“  ”.stnap ruoy dna-
.hguoht ,detartsurf yllaer saw I ”!tib A“
,llits kcots doots dna
.did I sa sgel ym dnuora morf sfeirb ym ekat ot nameltneg a fo hguone saw eh ,degilbo I
”.gnivael dna taoc ym gnikat m’I ecnetnes taht hsinif uoy fi tub raf siht uoy htiw kcuts ev’I“
,erus er’eW !haeY“   ”--ro deb rehto eht esu t’now eW
.sregnif gnol rehtar sih fo owt neewteb ti gnildnof
tcirtsnoc tsiaw ym tlef I neht dnA
”?enod er’uoy nehw su nioj annaw
”.tsenoh gnieb m’I fi boj yttihs a did I .siht ekil ton
,yug siht yb defrawd yletulosba saw I
,erofeb depmarc erew ew fI
yawllah taht ni tuo gnidnats ytfard gnitteg saw ti tub ,emit erom elttil a nevig retteb gnihtemos fo thguoht ev’dluoc I
.retaews sih ffo dils ylevitcudes eh retfa
,em woleb flehs eht revo lla daol ym nwolb ev’dluow I
,ym ni er’uoy em llet t’nod …uoy ezingocer I
netram derruf nworb elttil deracs A
.selacs sih rednu em hsurc dluoc taht emarf a htiw eerht toof xis ,egduj d’I ,saw eh elihw
.rebmemer t’nod yltsenoh I tub gniyas erew yeht tahw uoy llet d’I
,gninruter enot sih ni ssendlob taht
,krad eht ni su ees ot mih rof elbissopmi eb d’tI
’!’nikcuf er’uoy ,’nikcuf er’uoy fi
,hctorc sih debbarg I nehw ediw tnew seye siH
.htuom ym revo dnah delacs a tlef I
”.knird t’ndluohs uoy ni ti dloh t’nac uoy fi ,ega kcuf
evael dluow enoyreve taht tnaem ti neht ffo tnew mrala eht fi ,yeh tuB
.gurhs a htiw dednopser neht eH
…erofeb ti ekat dna hcuorc ot ydaer gninepo
.moorhtab roolf eht saw
.sladnas emos no deppils I retfa moor eht fo tuo em deggard yllacitcarp eH
”.ylrae kcab semoc eh esac ni
”.meht tuoba yrrow t’noD“
yawllah eht otni kcab
.gniht tnemom eht fo rups a saw tesolc srotinaj eht
;dnah ym ni yvaeh saw htgnel siH
.welb I lit ti gniod peek d’eh ro
”.od yllautneve ew nehw lliw uoy teb I ,heH“
ezilaer mih depleh ecaf ym gniees ebyam os
dna dren a s’etammoor yM“
.mih gnicaf saw ecaf gnihsulb dna ,deriah-yssem ,gnitnap ym woN
,rehtie ,elbirret t’nsaw llems eht
.dedisbus gnirekcins ruo retfa ekops nairB
.rediw gnitteg speek tsuj ti dna ,eussi on htiw ni seog ti os ,derepat ,ekil er’yehT
.pots em ekam ot hguone t’nerew
.egde eht revo em dnes ot gniog saw eh sa tsuj tuo llup dna esaet a eb ot dah rekcuf eht tub
”brutsiD ton oD“ saw sihT
.ytivitca fo dnik siht rof dedeen si tcatnoc lacisyhp tub
.retsemes txen moorhtab eht ni em htiw tuo ekam ot mih teg ot evah annog m’I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
doog yllaer gnitteg erew sgniht nehw tsuj
,dehsinif I emit eht yB
?dwel taht gnihtemos etupsid ot I saw ohw dnA
evah‒elohssa ym otni gud eugnot sih sa
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,eltneg sa tsuj erew stsurht wef txen ehT
,mih dniheb gnidnats elpoep fo seman erom dna erom ffo detsil eH ”…bocaJ ,maS
.gniyduts moor ym ro yrarbil eht ni gnittis fo retsemes eritne na retfa
,raewrednu ym fo meh eht ot neht ,sedis ym nwod
on…omoh a hcus si rewohnesiE rosseforp ,doG“
.tniop siht ta teg dluoc I tahw ekat d’I tub thgin eht ruovas ot tnaw did I ”…huh ,kciuQ“
.ni yaw rieht gnicrof won puorg eht gnicaf dna em fo ffo flesmih gnikat yllanif emit siht ,dednopser nairB
,stnap ym nettogrof d’ew hsur ruo nI
,mrod eht dniheb doots I dna nairB
.smra sih otni yltcerid flesym gnignilf dluow taht ot esnopser tseb eht thguoht I tub niaga snihprodne eht saw ti ebyaM
”…ees ot su tnaw t’ndid eh moor sih ni ffuts dah bocaJ neht
.ffo meht dehcni ylwols eh sa denessel stnap ym fo noisnet ehT
.retsemes lla no gnihsurc neeb d’I yug eht pu klat ot deganam I ,etammoor ym fo tnemegaruocne eht htiw tub
.pu daeh sih detfil tahT
...tsenoh eb ot ,lleW
”,eno eht s’taht ,haeY“
”.pu debul llits er’uoy epoh s'teL“
neewteb kcid sih htiw pu deldduh
.nepo rood ym deciton su fo rehtien taht etats knurd-tsul ruo ni
”.nam lortnoc ruoy fo tuo lla saw siht no emoC
,noitapicitna ni spil ym dekcil I
.kcab dloh t’ndluoc I
.niaga ekops .A.R eht sa gnicar taebtraeh sih leef dluoc I dna tsehc sih tsniaga desserp ylmrif saw ecaf yM
,sevlehs eht tsniaga dehsup saw I
.mih ot derepsihw I
ysub…m’I etammoor ym llet oT“
ruf siht lla rednu enob yllacitcarp dna xis toof evif m’I ,naem I
;hguoht ,sllats eht naht ecaps erom yaW
,ria moor egarots ytsum eht ni dloc elttil a pit tew ylthgils eht
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
”!won ti tnaw htob ew kniht I ,oslA
yrruFoS dna ytiniffA ruF no seidemoc yrruf citore setirw ohw
,retteb elttil a eb dluoc sthgil ehT
,hctib a adnik si s’aliM dna DnD gnivah era setammoor s’yrreJ llew ,hu tub
,revewoh rotpar ehT  .emahs
niks decreip tsomla yeht erehw tniop eht ot sedis ym gnihctulc
deye edis eH  ”.yllautneve emit tsrif gnizama na evah ll’I“
,lla ta ton yas ot si taht
.tihs emos ro elbat cidoirep eht gniziromem ot kcab og neht ,tuo su kcik ll’eH
,trapa ssa ym gnillup mih fo tca reehs eht morf naom a elfits ot dah I
eromyna dda dluow dekan em gniees elpoep kniht t’nod I
.nwod toof ym gnittup ,dias I ”,oN“
.detniop erom gniworg eciov ym ,deksa I ”?eW“
.od ot retteb gnihtemos dnuof sdnah sih noos dna
.erac t’ndid I tub
,redloc yna saw ti fI
.sfeirb ym tsniaga gnihsurb kcid s’rotpar eht leef llits dluoc I …won thgir tub
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.won srats nortuen otni pu gnihcnub yllacitcarp erew ew
.esolc em gnidloh ,edis ym no rehto eht dna htuom ym revo dnah eno dleh nairB elihwnaeM
”?tahw rof yrroS“
”?llats eht no stnap rieht tfel kcuf eht ohW“
.reduol tog ylno I dna repeed dna
.kcuf ot ecalp dab a ton
,tseivaeh eht gniyas
,nirg yrotaderp ,gums taht dah llits eh ,woN
,lla ni lla tuB .lla ta dekrow ev’dluoc yeht ni sa
.ecaf sih no kcab saw erised taht
,htaerb sih fo llems ehT
rethgit werg em no pirg siH
”?!ereh uoy era yhw
,mih morf yawa gnikcab flesym dnuof I dna
supmac no derueyov gnieb eno eht eb ot doog os tlef tI
,sgnaf sih erob eh sa
.enog yletelpmoc niaga ecno enot yrotaderp ,tnedifnoc taht ,dias eh
.esnopser ni derepmihw tsuj I
.tsiaw ym morf yawa yrossecca rehtael roop eht hsarht ot wam sih gnisu
,hctorc ym no dnah a tsuj ,sdrow oN
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  sisordysP yb ”brutsiD ton oD“
.won thgir seye fo riap eno tuoba derac yllaer ylno I tub
,oot ,denioj eh nooS .elggig
…elbmuts ot mih desuac I dna em hctac t’ndid eH   .aedi daB
,thginot bonk rood ym gnitaroced eno ylno eht t’nsaw I ekil skool tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ti fo dnoces yreve gnivol saw I dna efil ym ni detaloiv os tlef reven I
”.ffo stnap esoht teg dna pu tuhs woN“
.llaw mrod eht otni ylgnivol em gnimmals dneirfyob wen ,yllufepoh ,ym dna dednuop gnieb sedisni ym leef dluoc I sa
.kcab ti nrut dna elzzum sih ot pu dnah ym gnirb ot dah I
.niaga detpurretni tog ew litnU
.enim lla saw ti dna
,denepo rood eht sa noos sa edisni em dehsup dna derepsihw eh
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.rehto eht yb dewollof
.tleb ym ta deggut yldwel rotpar eht sa
.suoretsiob dna derruls
gniwollof ylgnilliw saw raey roinuj sih ni rotpar rats llabtoof tnedifnoc sihT
,ebab thgin lla gniog er’eW“
.secaf kcurtsbmud s'rehto hcae ta derats eW
,emit siht gnidnirg ro gnisaet on saw erehT
,eromyna suovren t’nsaw I
,dessap deklaw retsemes eht fo dne eht gnitarbelec spuorg dna selpuoc rehto sa sedis ym no hcnelc thgil dna eporg ssa yreve htiW
.ecaf sih fo tsom demusnoc elims luftsul sih sa demaelg
”taht evol dluow mrod ruo dna ytiruces supmac erus m’I ,ahaH“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sisordysP yb
”-B ,kcul dab tsuj s’tI“
.mih dniheb rood eht gnittuhs
.siht ekil t’nsaw taht tub ,tuo trihs ym gnurw I elihw gnitnuoc ton
no‒seitnap neve, lleh‒sanadnab ,skcos
,depacse ew emit eht yb yleritne trihs ym ogrof ot dediced I
.enod erew ew emit eht yb tnirpmi na tfel kcab ym fi desirprus eb t'ndluow I
,denruter sdnah s’rotaderp eht
eht tub ecaps eht fo esuaceb saw ti ebyaM
deppots ylkciuq eh esuac
.derehsu gnieb saw I ekil erom saw tI   .yllaer ,t’nsaw I...tsenoh
.pu krow ot drah os tneps I eglub eht pu gnileef
.dliw og em gnikam dna sregnif owt neewteb gniht eht gnigassem saw eh hguohtlA
.stneduts egelloc gnoma roivaheb elbisnopserri fo sdnuos eht raeh dluoc I meht fo eno yreve dna hcae nI
.su hctac did enoemos fi nwod llup ot gnihtemos evah tsael ta d’I
.doom eht niur d’taht ekil leef I