,htrof dna kcab ylthgil gnicnaD
denaorg stnanmer tsol fo selip eht sa ecnalab dnif ot gnilggurts teef erab sih
dnuora kool tsal eno koot eH
.ecalp ni ylefas llits saw elfir reh taht gnirusne
.meht esu yllaer dluoc eW“
sciler htiw dellif
.ereht nwod erom s’erehT“ .dias eh
.talf tsomla tey ,sdnah sih naht regral ylerab saw tI
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,detser dah ti hcihw ni evocla eht morf ti gniveirter ylluferac
.skcor eht hguorht gniwolb dniw eht ot netsil
,smra sih gnidloF
,sirbed fo reyal retuo eht edisa dehsup ylluferac eh ,nwod gninaeL
,elbac eht tcarter ot nageb neD
tresed eht hguorht yaw sti erot
,arabmA ta kcab er’ew
.muh gnilward yllacimhtyhr sti nigeb ot enigne eht rof gnitiaw
,dna sdniw evitcaoidar
”!teef ytriht rehtona nwod em rewol“ detuohs eh
.meht tsniaga ylivaeh gnikrow saw emit taht flesreh ot timda ot dah neD neve tub
”.thgir saw apdnarG“ ,dias eh ”drow yM“
.esuom llams eht deppiy ”!oN“
,nekorb dna prahs tlef nopu doots eh taht segde eht fo lareveS
?fo tuo sesserd ekam ot sesu annaT aM taht stcejbo ynihs eht rebmemer uoy od …mmmh ,ekiL“
?nwo rieht no dekrow taht sgniht dliub yeht t’ndluoc yhw ,erew yeht dias elpoep sa trams sa erew snamuh tneicna esoht fi
saw ffiksrevoh ehT
,spil sih gnisruP
,dnuorg ralugerri eht morf delf swodahs eht
redluohs s’nexiv eht dnuora gnuh taht elfir ehT
”?neerub emat ruoy ekil siht sI
dehsuh worg ot gnitrats eciov reh
tnemom a rof depag waj s’retsgnuoy ehT
.snmuloc gnillarips dna detsiwt fo selip ni
.retlehs rof ecalp on meht gnivael
,gab sih ni ecived llams eht gnihctulC
”.neht kcab ti dellac yeht tahw tsuj s’tahT
.saw ylurt ti dlo woh tsuj derednow acuL
.tcejretni ot regae
.dias rehtafdnarg ym ekil tsuj s’tI“
.ecaf sih fo tsom desacne taht sesnel kciht eht no gnitsiwt
,kcapkcab sih otni yrevocsid eht gnidilS
- dellac erew yeht ,sciler
,egapbew rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”.shtnom owt tsomla ni elfir ym rof lioc rewop degrahc ylluf a dah t’nevah I
ylthgils derevaw parts niht a yb
tsiaw sih dnuora droc eht fo llup prahs hcae
mih htaeneb morf tuo yaws dnuorg eht tlef esuom gnuoy eht ,gut eht htiW
,dias eh ”thgil sesu tI“
,enivar eht fo htdaerb eht gnola yaw eno dekool eH
,ebyC nosilA yb ”!skooB cimoC ruoy tegroF t'noD“ saw sihT
ruoy sa dam sa er’uoY .decnivnoc m’I won ,lleW ”?skoob cimoC“
.evoba raf morf eciov s’neD emac ”?taht saw tahW“
,enivar eht fo mottob eht sa dekool ecno dah
”?taht dellac ti s’yhw oS“
- msahc eht fo mottob eht enil ot demees erusaert detalumucca fo htrow sedaced ehT .rehto eht neht
.enivar eht fo esab eht ta mih tem taht thgis eht ta llirht yffig a tlef eh ,os nevE
.essaverc eht otni ,hcni yb hcni
tnedor eht delbmurg ”won tuoba woH“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,thgilnus tnatsid eht ta ecnalg ot daeh sih gnitlit ,pu dellac eh
,selggog sih detsujda esuom eht
”sdees htiw gnihtyna od t’nseod tI“
,ria eht hguorht yltnatsni tnes eb dluoc srettel nehw syad fo seirots
.yrekcom rettib ni
”.teb I ,oot sgniht lufesU
syad fo shtym neve dna
?rehtegot sgnirts ehs taht selcric ehT
,seitilibapac lacigam-raen dna
.tesnus s’gnineve gnicnavda eht tsniaga
lacigolonhcet gnizama fo
.hcum sa naom dna nialpmoc ot yticapac eht etiuq dah taht edart parcs eht ni nosrep rehto on tsomla nwonk dah emit taht ni dna
.redduhs tneciter a htiw sdrawpu detrats ffiksrevoh eht sa tleb-
.ylper t’ndid acuL
”!pu yaw eht no em pord t’nod tsuJ“
”?dnif uoy did tahW“
.meti eht eveirter ot kcap sih otni dehcaer eh
.smeti detauqitna
.thgilnus rebma eht ni ylniatrecnu ciler eht ta gnireep
,wenk eh ,ffuts doog ehT
.gnirekcib s’noinapmoc sih ot suoivilbo saw
.efil raed rof droc elisnet eht dehctulc eh
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,esuom eht denialpxe
.thgiew reh detsujda ehs sa
.noinapmoc enilef reh ta ezag reh gniworran
.saw evort eht peed woh aedi on dah eh
,kcab ti barg ot pu gnihcaeR
”!ydaer m’I“ .sgut drah
”.meht esu ot desu yeht ,stneicna ehT
- llew sa selat eseht elpoep rehto dlot dah rehtafdnarg sih ,esruoc fO
.kciuq eb ot evah ll’eW“ .dias eh
ydob reppu sih desae esuom eht
.seenk sih neewteb ylefas kcapkcab sih dils esuom gnuoy eht
.ylsuoixna ,niaga dellac ehs ”?ti tog uoY“
”?krow ti t’nseod yhw oS“
,nodicorev yrgna yllaicepse na fo swaj eht gnipacse ylerab
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.esuom eht ot kcab sucof reh gninrut erofeb ,neD deppans
ria eht hguorht eldnurt ot nageb dna
.senigne eht fo dnuos gniworg eht revo
”!skooB cimoC ruoy tegroF t'noD“
,ecafrus sti desserac eh ,taht dna yaw siht ti gninruT
ehca prahs a gnisuac
. .ydob s’tnedor llams eht hguorht
.cirbaf gniwollib ydruts eht ni srae reh gnisacne
,edis reh yb regit ynwarb eht ta kool ot daeh reh gninruT
,thgir krow ti ekam ot redro ni esle gnihtemos evah ot evah ekam yeht gnihtyreve seod yhW
”.placs s’nlaW dlo no ecil ekil ereh revo yaw rieht gnilwarc trats sremialc‘ eht erofeb gnol eb t’now ti ,tuo steg drow eht ecnO
.mih dednuorrus msahc eht fo ria llits eht dna
,spets luferac wef a gnikaT
,acuL dias ”taht naht retteB“
.rof gud eb ot dedeen
neeb dah enivar eht otni tnecsed ehT
,tip eht fo llaw deggarc eht tsniaga toof eno gnitnalP
,don ot nageb esuom ehT ”?erus uoy erA
”.dam s’eh taht dias ydobyreve yhw ees I kniht I
.ti detanimulli dna kcitswolg a eerf dekculp eh
,msahc eht fo pil eht dnuora sregnif sih gnihctulC
”.gniht eht s’tahT
neeb evah tsum thguoht esuom eht tahw ni aera eht dehcuot dah taht thgil larutan tsrif eht
,edaced a flah revo rof regit eht nwonk dah eH
,ecalp otni kcab ksam gnihtaerb sih gnidilS
.reyalp e-dees a dellac tsuj s’tI“
.detnurg eh ”?yllaeR“
.regit eht deppans ”!yeH“
.mih htaeneb detfihs dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.detrons regit eht
ecnO“ .yltnedifnoc ,dias ehs
.noisserpxe yraew a noinapmoc sih evag esuom eht
,efil raed rof egrog eht otni dednepsus mih dleh taht elbac eht otno dehctulc eH
”?eloh nmad eht fo tuo s’eh litnu“
”?wohemos cisum otni sdees snrut tI“
,retsum dluoc eh sa erac hcum sa htiW
,hteet sih neewteb yletaciled kcits-wolg eht gnihctulC
,sthgiferif nepo htiw sretnuocne esolc ynam devivrus gnivah
,noitcnuf tneicna sti mrofrep ot elba eb dluow eno siht fi derednow eH
.llew sa ti tfel dah cigam eht fi ro
sirbed htiw dekcap
.worbeye na desiar regit ehT ”.skoob cimoc
stcejbo elbissopmi hcus nehw
ees dluoc I ,elbbur eht hguorht gniggid ereht nwod saw I elihw taht raews I .retteb raF“
redart ro regnevacs ynnac eht yb gnikcip rof epir
.epor dedroc elisnet eht no pirg reh esae ylwols ot nageb neD ,evoba raF
dluoc taht sgniht fo elbapac
,renwo eht deppans ”!yeH“
,trons evisired a htiW
,seinapmoc elpitlum rof retirw GPR potelbat a si ohw ,ebyC nosilA yb
.s’nexiv eht naht repeed eno
”.etunim a em eviG“
.dlrow eht ni yaw rieht ekam ot regae
tcejbo eht depsarg regit eht ,ylismulC
.regit eht ot ti gnireffo ,dias eh ”ereH“
,hteet dettirg hguorht regit eht deksa
.essaverc eht fo mir retuo eht no ,gnileenk-flah
.snug dna slioc rewoP“
,ylsuoludercni ,dias eh
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.swap ralucsum s’nlaW hguorht ylnrets ti gnidaerht
,revewoh ,esuom ehT
,taes eht otni gnilffuhS .deksa eh
,sdrawnwod noinapmoc rieht esae ot ylidaets dekrow yeht
”!skooB cimoC ruoy tegroF t'noD“:yojne esaelP
.dellac ehs ”?won tuoba woH“
,pih reh dekcehc ehs ylsuoituaC
.elkcuhc desumeb a evag regit eht ,mih ediseb taes eht otni nwod gnipmulS
.sraey ynam os rof
.tekcop a no tser ot emac sregnif sih litnu delbmuf acuL
.srehtael sih ffo gnitsud
.smuhc sih dna nalceD zzub ll’I
”,dniw fo gnikaepS“
?woH“ .ti koohs eH .detrons nlaW ”.cisum sekam tI .reyalp-e-dees a s’tI“
”gninialpmoc potS“ ”?he
- eurt eb reve dluoc seirots eht fi derednow eh
did eh sa dna ,enivar eht fo mottob eht ta
.ti esu ot deen eht evah t’ndluow ehs taht deyarp ehs dna
”.hcum yrev uoy knaht ,ydnad dna enif tsuj hO“
,rethgit eht lla elbac eht dnuora
.spool ydruts gnol otni kcab elbac elisnet eht gnidniw ,neD detcejretni
”zeeG“         ”.esaelp uoy fi ,thginot emit emos emoh teg ot ekil d’I .snrut dniw eht erofeB“
,trohs fo riap a elbac eht evag eH
noiger eht fo ecafrus eht fo hcum taht
,elbat eht edisa gnivohs ylregaE
,tnedicni etanutrofnu eno ni
,pu dooh reh dellup ehs ylkciuQ
”.su stih dniw der eht erofeb sruoh owt tuoba tog ev’eW
,ecneitapmi htiw degde saw eciov reH
dniw der eht fo sbrab nehsa eht fi toj a reh pleh t’ndluow stellub eht tub ,ybraen nopaew reh peek ot hguone lufesu s’ti ,thguoht eh ,eruS
,nopaew a deirrac ohw eno ylno eht saw neD
.smra sih dedlof acuL
.gab sih otni kcab tcafetra eht gnikcut
.redluohs reh dnuora elbac eht gninetsaf ,deggurhs neD
,gnitser saw eh litnu pu hcni yb hcni delbmarcs acuL
.ylregae etiuq deddon acuL
,nepo ti gnikcilF
.cigam fo mrof tseurt eht eb ylno
”eibmoz eganeet yag a saw I“ fo rohtua dna
”?nlaW ,ereht elttil a xaler ot tnaw uoy oD“
,tleb sih ot nwod gnihcaeR
.otni flesmih nettog dah esuom gnuoy eht tahw tsuj niaga ecno derednow acuL
,nettogrof dna dedracsid
.snialp tresed ykcor eht evoba
”ti tog tsomla ev’I“   ebyC nosilA yb
taes nrow dlo sih gninetsaf
,sregnif ygdup sih htiw taht dna yaw siht sedis ekil-ksid sti gninrut
.tnemom taht ta mih ot derrucco tsuj ylno dah aedi eht hguoht sa
,stcejbo detrossa eht no nwod tes eh ylsuoituaC
”hA“ .eloh eht otni
,eloh eht morf kcab tcejbo llams eht dils eh
,syad retteb nees yletinifed dah tI
.tcejbo llams a dnuora gnipparw sregnif sih ,demialcxe eh
,noinapmoc sih ot dnif sih denialpxe esuom eht ,enivar eht fo edis eht tsniaga teef sih gnitnalP
.edis eno ot elbat latem nekorb dlo na gnirehsu
drawrof tloj prahs a koot ffiks eht sa
.ylsuoixna ,regit eht deppans ”!yob ,no emoC“
.dnuora decnalg eh sa
?uoy dlot rehtafdnarg ruoy tahw taht sI
”tseggib eht fo enO“
,dnuorg ykcor eht tsniaga teef reh gnitnalP ”!pu em luah“
,ti detlit eH .pu ti dleh dna
”!elbaulav gnihtemos dnuof ev’ew em llet ,esaelp hO ?lles nac ew ffutS ?slioc rewop dnif uoy did ,oS .mih erongI“
.yllanif ,deksa eh ”?od ti s’tahW“
”?ereht nwod luah doog a ti sI“
.tonk a otni mrof ot hcamots s’esuom eht gnisuac ,ydaetsnu
,sreltub lanosrep ekil srenwo rieht no tiaw dluoc senihcam nehw ro
.yks eht morf nwod niar dluow
”cisum ekam t’nseod thgiL“ ”.cigam namuH“
- enivar eht fo mottob eht gnola yaw sti deremmihs thgil wolley yzah A
,troffe desucof ylprahs ni dettirg hteet reh
.detned dna derettab ,dlo
,wolg eht nI .sedaced
”.slluf ffiks lareves teg ot elba eb dluohs ew smaet eerht htiW
stsif reh dehcnelc ehS
”acuL ,rehtafdnarg
,esuom eht detuohs
enecs eht no tsrif eb dna tuo teg ot hsur eht
.gniog teg ot evah ew“
deraperpnu yllufeow meht tfel dah
?sesserd fo tuo cisum ekam sremialc‘ ehT ?tahW“
.tip eht fo ssenkrad eht hguorht pu kcab ecnalg ot daeh sih gninrut
,gnitpurretni ,regit eht dias
,oga sruoh eerht ylno etis eht fo drow draeh dah oirt eht ecniS
- taht sa hcus stcejbO
,thgilnus fo ezah tnatsid eht otni gniwolleB
”neht worromot ylrae evirra eW“
”,lliw uoy tahw knihT“
.enivar eht fo noziroh eht dnuora htrof dna kcab ylsuoituac gnitrad seye reh elihw eht lla
.kcab ti debbarg acuL ,yltneitapmI
.sgnul sih morf ria eht debbor raen nmad gnivah tnecsed sih fo ssensuoiracerp eht
.denialpxe eh ”ksid a sdeen tI“
.gut rehtona evag nlaW
,srotingi eht pu gnitrats ni emit on detsaw neD
,evoba morf deohce eciov rehtonA
./moc.etisbewsebyc//:ptth
.tnedni llams hcae gnileef
,sregnevacs eerht eht fO
”?luah doog a ti sI“
sserP straeH peeD yb
,noisufnoc htiw degde eciov a htiw nliW deksa
.esuom eht deksa ehs
ssendoog-ot-tsenoh lautca
.dekrow ylerab yeht tub ,esruoc fo ,meht fo ynam nees dah acuL
.gniremmihs seye s’retnuh erusaert eht ni tnemeticxe fo tnilg eht
,neD deksa ”?snug ekiL“
.mih dlot dah rehtafdnarg sih taht seirots eht derebmemer acuL
dna sevac eht ni edih ot desu dna sbuc erew ew nehw ekiL .cisum sekam riA“
,neD detroter
.ecaf desumeb sih ssorc krims tfos a tel tub pleh t’ndluoc acuL ,siht gnicitoN
fo sredart eht gnoma ecirp hgih a thguac syawla
,wonk uoY .sesserd dna sreyalp e-deeS
si yrots s’yadot dna
,neD detsisni ”snoitseuq eht evas spahrep uoy dluoC“ ”?od ti seod tahW“
,siht sa smeti hcus tuoba mih thguat dah rehtafdnarg siH
,kaolc neloow kciht a ni dekced regit ytfeh a
.mih dleh taht elbac eht fo ssenidruts eht gnikcehc ni emit on detsaw acuL dna