,derettum sedemihcrA
,thguoht eht ta delkcuhc syawla dah eniledaM
.ni elif ot nageb sremotsuc gninrom fo evaw tsrif eht sa
.gniliar eht no gnidnal dna
,ssem eht revo delzzup ehS
”,rehtegot etuc os era owt uoY“
nirg a derahs yehT
.eno eert tneicna dna éfac eht ekam ot
seltit eht revo nar ylfeirb walc reH
”.siht dnif ot emit gnol a em koot tI
.nogard eht morf noops eht koot dna nikpan a no walc sih depiw eh nehT
kciuq tub eltneg ,segap dewolley ,dlo hguorht gnippilf nageb dna
,nageb hsur eht sa noos sa tsuJ
,yrtnuoc a gninnur ekil eb ton yam tI
.seton eht ta gnikop
.deyats dworc eht fo noitcarf a ylno dna tuo deitpme pohs eeffoc eht
.lliuq reh nwod gnittup
.tsehc reh ot noitativni eht gnihctulc saw ohw eniledaM ot pu dekool eH
,yltsenoh ,em rof tnemeticxe hcum oot neeb sah sihT“
”,htiw pu siht naelc ot gnihtemos teg og ll’I“
.eninazzem eht ot pu sdaeh rieht deppihw meht fo htoB
”,noitnem ot togrof eh tahW“
”,krow ot kcab teg ot em deripsni ylniatrec s’ti
repap fo eceip knalb a rof dehcaer dnah reh
”.yad eno netsil thgim I
nalhguoC ”uorihS“ yaJ yb
.dekram snoitacol eht ta decalp eb dluoc sevlehs eht no teknirt rehto yrevE
,dehcuot d’ehs straeh eht llA
,koon reh otni kcab dna sriats eht nwod deppils nogard ehT
,thgirb eht elihw
,denniht dworc eht htiW
,swalc ykcits htiw ruf sih elssut ot em stnaw ikuY kniht t’nod I tuB“
.derehtaew dna dlo lla
.erusopmoc reh niur ot gninetaerht yoj eht kcab dleh ehs ,htaerb a htiW
,sriats eht pu dehsad dna riahc eht fo tuo deppils ehS
”.sriatsnwod tekcub pom eht gnirb ll’I“
,sknird eerf htiw meht thgiled dluow eniledaM
”,pohs siht dnuora yats uoy yhw ees I kniht I“
.sruoy ekil efil a gnivil retfa llud ylbirret mees tsum pohs eeffoc a gninwO“
.daeh sih koohs dna delims okikuY
.sdoog fo elas eht lortnoc ot stekram fo sniahc tsav gninwo ro sreknab sa selor pu gnikat
.tsehc s’eniledaM ta dehctulc kcab dekcilf srae sih yaw ehT
”.llew os gniog t’nsi gniyduts ruoy ekil kool uoY“
,meht no revoc lanigiro rieht dah regnol on ynaM
.nirg suoveihcsim a htiw dias eniledaM
taeh gnihcrocs fo tnemom a rof mottob eht ta gnidnal
,dah aralA sdrow emas eht derettum dna pot eht no dnah sih decalp eH
.deddon ydneW .deksa ehS
”,okikuY ,uoy rof aet neerg-esor A“
”.gniyduts ot kcab teg uoy tel ll’I“
”.gniypoc dna gnitaehc stneverP“
,serutaerc gniticxe dna wen gniretnuocne
,yllautca ,lleW
,revo delppot saw gum reH
,emoh ta eseht evah I“
,oga sedaced ynaM
saw puc eht togrof I
”,ekawa s’eh nehw ylnO“
.stseug reh ot tuo ekat ot sknird erom wef a deraperp ehs dna
.tresed eht ni tsol dna deirub-flah
detsaor nogarD fo etsat a rof llA
,sevlehs eht dellif semulov dnuob-rehtaeL
,selbat reh revo doots
.artsehcro yzal a ni pohs eht tuoba dellim
”…kniht I ,rehtegot emoc ot strats gnihtyreve erehw trap eht yllaer si siht
.gnihtyna tuoba deticxe ylbirret gnieb rehtom ym rebmemer t’nac I“
.krow reh ni dedepminu saw reyolpme sih erus gnikam dna ,syart pird eht dna senihcam eht tuo gninaelc
.woleb roolf eht ot nwod gnidilg
.taht fo yna rof erac t’ndid eniledaM
”!enoyreve rof esuoh eht no era seeffoC“
”.dessucof uoy peek pleh thgim ti thguoht I
.ssem eht niatnoc ot gab a otni skoob dna slliuq deyortsed eht gnippord
,rehtom reh ekil hcum ydaerla saw ehs syaw ynam nI
,delims eniledaM
.seton s’ydneW fo pot no koob eht tes eniledaM
,tcatnoc eht ta elbatrofmocnu tib a dekool eH
.taht naht sroolf erom ynam rof hguone egral ydaerla saw eert eht taht wenk ehs
ezah gnitrofmoc ,eltneg a ni tuoba gnuh ria dehcrot fo elkcit elat-llet ehT
.dekrims eniledaM
,gniyduts teg ot deen I“
.draoh reh saw ,ereh ,sihT
.sriats eht nwod tfel aralA dna
.redluohs s’ydneW no dnah reh tup dna
eulav fo stcejbo dna serusaert
.derettum sedemihcrA
”,tnetxe siht ot ti gnisu emit emos ekat yam tI
.seirtnuoc gnidael
,yrasrevinna rieht no raey yrevE
.imA ,uoy rof maerc deppihw htiw deppot ,tohs osserpse artxe na dna
”,decrofnier gniliar eht tog I nosaer a
;seye reh erofeb dedlofnu seirots eritnE
,lliuq derehtaef kciht a htiw gnilbbircs eb dluow dnah enO
”,eniledaM ssiM ,syawla sa gnizama sllems tI“
,dehctiwt eson s’enoyrevE
.denibmoc yad eht fo tser eht dluow yeht naht ruoh na ni sknird erom gnivres
”.snoisses yduts reh gnirud redro ot desu rehtom ruoy gniht emas eht saw tahT“
,siht xif ot gniog er’ew
”...skoob wen droffa t’nac I-
,teiuq yllausu si roolf dnoces ehT“
”,rocéd wen rof gnikool ma I sevren ruoy no steg eh fi tub
a fo gnileef eht dnatsrednu yllaer
.roolf driht a gniworg saw
.lehctas ’sedemihcrA otni epolevne eht deppils ehS
.htuom sih otni ti gnippop dna
.esuoh eht no s’ti ,wonk I“ .dias ehs
,trats depleh d’ehs serutnevda eht
.revo dezalg seye
s’erehT“ .deppans sedemihcrA
”-dna -dna stcejorp no dniheb ydaerla m’I dna ,worromot-
.elims yoc a htiw dehsulf eniledaM ”.uoy ,hsuh hO“
.ylhsipeehs dennirg imA dna delkcuhc ikuY
syalpsid puc og-ot eht llifer ot deunitnoc sedemihcrA
.esop citsejam a ni roteirporp s’éfac eht tciped ot demees taht
,ydneW ot txen tas dna liat reh htiw riahc a pu dellup ehS
.skoobtxet eht fo eno pu gnikcip ,denworf okikuY
.écnaif sih ot revo gnidils ,dias imA
si yrots s’yadot dna
,ecaf s’imA morf maerc deppihw eht epiw ot revo dehcaer okikuY
,reh htiw tis ot tnemom teiuq a ekat dluow ssetsoh nogard eht ecno naht eroM
.niaga riahc reh ot ydneW dediug yltneg dna sedirts tfiws ni meht neewteb ecnatsid eht dessorc eniledaM ”-dna
etteutats nogard edaj a saw erehT
.ecamirg a htiw dedda aralA ”,gninaelc dnA“
,xaw nedlog fo daw a htiw delaes ,epolevne etihw ,llams a tuo dellup eH
.ereht dnas eht ot ecitsuj od reve lliw sdrow kniht t’nod I ,lleW“
.roolf tsrif eht ot kcab ynoclab eht ffo tpel eh dna
eton dekaos-eeffoc a gnitfil
”,gnihtyrevE .eM .lleT
.woleb roolf tsrif eht otno tuo dekool taht eninazzem roolf-flah a saw pohs eeffoc eht fo noitrop sriatspu ehT
,yenom gnitsaw ruoy tuo tniop dluow I“
.evisruc ni nogard eht ot desserdda
regnif a koot eH
.yllufyalp ,eson sih dekcilf okikuY dna eugnot sih tuo kcuts imA
,stneidergni eht gniraperp ysub saw sedemihcrA ,elihwnaeM
gnihsarc gnihtemos fo dnuos ehT
.htmraw sti yojne ot gnimees ,eeffoc eht ta kaeb sih dekop dna
,noitaicerppa fo wac eltneg a evag eH
netfo ehS .demool kcolb s’retirw dna senildaed sa
.eniledaM ssiM ,yllautcA“
,sreltna reh diova ot detlit elzzum sih
”!uoy knaht ,hsog ym hO“
”,eciton ot slwob ragus decalpsim ta gnilbmurg ysub oot erew uoy thguoht I ereh dnA“
”.diarfa m’I ,senildaed ruoy teem ot hguone raf teg t’nod uoy fi hcum htrow t’nsi ssergorp lleW“
su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.elttil a tsuj xaler selcsum sih leef dluoc nogard eht tub kcab dekcilf srae derehtaef ,llat siH
”,dlo snoitide elpuoc a ylno
”,siht redro t’ndid I …I“
,decalper segap dah emoS
!uoy ni tnadnuba eb tsum noitaripsnI
,tuoba derettacs erew sdrac-euC
,dennirg rohtua ehT
”,taert a er’uoy ,eniledaM ,uoy knaht ,hO“
.ria eht dellif emalf fo raor dna elkcarc railimaf ehT .erif dna
.sdliw eht otni tuo nworht tnecs rieht
”,reh htiw evil-il t’nod uoy
”,diarfa m’I ,yrutnec siht ot tnaveler gnihtoN“
I“ .deppord traeh s’ydneW
tsuj sruoh rof ereh tis ot evol d’I
,heH“ ”.ot evah t’nod yllaer uoy ,tuo gnipleh rof uoy knahT“
.ylsuoiduts no dehctaw ohw ,ydneW dna okikuY htob ot lleps gninaelc reh gnitartsnomed saw aralA
a htiw dehsiws tI
elbat eht no nwod yart eht decalp eniledaM
.ni demihc eniledaM
.éfaC tsaoR nogarD eht fo
fle krad ehT .dias ehS
.taes reh ni kcab denael dna nwod koob eht tes ydneW
”?tuoba egassap eht s’tahW“
.lleb eht fo elknit a htiw denepo rood ehT
.éfac a sa sselgninaem dna llams sa gnihtemos htiw derehtob snogard weF
.retnuoc eht fo doow eht nrub ot ton sa os bals elbram a otno lwob toh eht derewol yltneg ehS
,sdnah reh ni puc eht deldarc ylregae
!elbigel era seton eht ,swen dooG“
.okikuY dnuora smra reh gnipparw ,deirc ydneW
.secalp suoirav ni s’X elttil
,hguoht lufituaeb era sgnineve ehT
,dias ehS ”,gnizama lla er’uoY“
”?tol a ereh yduts ehs diD
,detseggus eniledaM
.ydneW ot revo gninael ,derepsihw eniledaM
.efil s’renwo éfac eht morf skcank-kcink suoirav eht yb detacramed ,snoitces otni pu nekorb erew skoob ehT
eroc eulb-yks a htiw semalf wolley-etihw ,yltsohG
.neppah cigam nwo reh ekam ot repap ot sdrow tup ot deirt yletarepsed ehs sa ro
roolf eht otno liat reh fo hsiws a htiw retnuoc eht fo tuo deklaw dna delims eniledaM
.ymedaca eht ta sessalc reh rof yduts dna tis dluoc ydneW os rehtegot dellup erew wef a
.dnuora mih tuohtiw ekil er’uoy tahw ees ot etah d’I“
”.uoy ksa ot detnaw ew gnihtemos dah eW
”?eeffoc eht ekil uoy oD“
”?pmurg a syawla eh sI“
,erehwyreve naem I
timda I“ ”.ti evol I tuB“
daeh s’tneduts eht sa dezaf lla ta ton
”.htiw pu emoc ev’uoy tahw daer rehtar hcum d’I
”.ynomerec eht rof éfac eht tuo tner su tel d’uoy gnipoh fo dnik erew ew
ro stseuq no gniog srerutnevda elbaton fo stnuocca detareggaxe ylegral erew emos
.dettimda eniledaM
.rehtom reh ekil boj a teg ot elba saw ehs litnu loohcs rof yenom reh evas ot gnivah
.petstoof hcae htiw dekaerc sriats gnillaripS
”,meht no slleps cigam-itna evah yehT“ .degnahcnu
.eunitnoc noitom eht tel tub ,denworf eH
,desnet liat reh nehT
.delims eniledaM
,doog ylerar erew yehT
,tnemyap rieht ekat ot desufer tsomla dna demaeb ehS
.yltnangidni wac dna pael worc desirprus eht gnikam
.nigeb neve ot erehw niatrecnu ,nwod kcab gnittes neht
,ynoclab eht revo dekool dna doots eniledaM
sehcnarb s’eod eht fo eno gnihctulc ,worc kcalb-tej a doots sreltna reh nI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.ffo fle eht devaw ehs sa dias eniledaM ”,relles-tseb
.das wohemos demees seye ydaeb siH
,egaugnal tsol-gnol a ni nettirw sdrow dah noilladem dlog egral rehtonA
.esirpretne ni dna efil ni htob rentrap s’eniledaM saw eH
”?gniog ssergorp eht s’woH“
.htaerb reh thguac nogard yarg-mrots eht dna ,nwod deid semalf eht ,yllautnevE
”.hguoht degnis pu dne thgim yehT“
.dedda ylitsah ehS ”.elihwhtrow
!deirram gnitteg er’eW“
.enustik egnaro eht ot ti gnissap ,delims ehS
etalocohc artxe htiw oniccuppac a dna“
”.em fo daeha gnikniht rof uoy knaht
muh tfos a delbmur taorht s’eniledaM
dekrep sdaeh s’enoyrevE
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
ecitcarp fo sedaced ynaM
meht neewteb ecnatsid trohs eht dessorc eniledaM ”.ksat-itlum nac I“
.sevil ruo fo trap eguh a hcus neeb stI“
tnemeticxe sih gnieeS
,hcum oot devol gnieb fo psuc eht no tsuj erew srehto
.ereht tuo elbatrofmocnu tlef I nevE
”!skoobtxet dlo ,gnirob esoht teg og s’teL !ydneW ,no emoC“
.dnuober neeb gnivah
,yletaidemmi krow ot tes okikuY dna ydneW
”.sdrow lautca evlewt nwod nettirw evah thgim I kniht I dna
.erutnevda na fo erom hcum taht yad s’enoemos gnikam fo wolgretfa eht ni gnithgiled
.htrof gnitsrub sraet fo evaw hserf a ,detroter ydneW
,efil ym ni selpmet tresed fo elpuoc a ot neeb evah I ,lleW“
,decudortni eb ot deen
,gnitfihs dna gnikahs edisni snaeb eht
,lliks a sa gnitirw poleved ot ecneitap eht dah reven I“
,sknaht reh evag ylkciuq ydneW
eye s’eniledaM fo renroc eht ta denrub raet A
.detadtuo ecnis gnol snoitatnacni dna slleps cigam
.nirg eltneg a otni gnittilps morf elzzum reh pleh t’ndluoc eniledaM
.dias eniledaM ”,lla ta toN“
.modnar ton erew sgnikram eht taht hguoht ees dluoc eye deniart a htiw esohT
,denialpmoc yeht hguoht ,tuB
,tnemom a retfa dias ehS
lwob nori-tsac yvaeh a fo esab eht ta dekcil
”,em esucxe esaelP“
.tnatropmi ssel on sI“
”,no gniog saw tahw meht dlot I litnu em gniggub pots t’ndluow sexof eht
.liat reh fo hsiws a htiw dias eniledaM
.seye sih ni elims a fo tsohg eht htiw ,dedda eH
sreltna s’ydneW morf nwod deppoh ,worc eht ,yeroC
,dehgual aralA ”!owt uoy no emoC“
.snoitces owt neewteb tas ebolg egral A
.elbat eht dnuora roolf eht gnippom nageb eh sa deksa imA
”,smees ti sa dab os ton s’ti ,lleW“
.erofeb noitseuq siht draeh dah ehS
”.tekcub dna pom eht thguorb ew saW“ ,dedda imA
.deeps rof edisa tpews ssenilnaelc
,rehtona eno tsniaga derettalc yeht sa esion fo artsehcro na gnikam
.devirht dna werg llits hcihw
delims eniledaM
.dnoces a rof desuap neht
.rohtua nevle na tas nwod selbat owT
”,nac uoy ,esruoc fO“
.eod eht egassam ot nageb dna kcab reh no dnah yvaeh a tup eniledaM ”-dam eb lliw mom-
,roteirporp eht ot ruovaf a sa
.evoba gnilcric dna
”?sllaw fo ffo ecnuob uoy oD
”,sruoloc gniylf htiw ssap ll’uoy wonk I
,sriats eht pu dettort dna
.llif-er s’nortap reh gniraperp
pets nedoow hcae otni dessecer stovid ediw ,tfos dah yeht dna
looc si yks thgin eht tub
.meht nopu detsiof serusserp eht ot ni gnivig fo sngis on htiw ydruts deniamer yeht
”?lleps eht em hcaet uoy dluow
revo saw wohs eht wonk gnihctaw llits esoht gnittel
.enustik etihw eht ot txen gum elpmis eht decalp ehs sa dias eniledaM
.egap eht ydneW gnidnah
.ynoclab eht sdrawot daeh reh deddon ehS
,taerg od lliw uoy ,ydneW ,esnesnoN“
.thgiled ni tuo dennaf sliat ruof siH
.elims mraw a otni tilps elzzum reH
sllips eeffoc ynam oot morf sniats dah yeht won tuB
”,ti wonk uoy erofeb kcab eb ll’I“
.erahs ot taert laiceps a dna
.reh dniheb deliart ti sa spets eht diova ot detfil liat
”!noitaripsni htiw gnitsrub eb d’I
”.meht evah nac uoY“ ,dereffo eH
sknird eerht htiw gnola ti dessap dna gab elbalaes a otni snaeb eht depoocs eniledaM
owt eht morf flesreh desucxe ehS
”snaeB eeffoC detsaoR nogarD“:yojne esaelP
.roolf dnoces eht no sllaw eht denil skcank-kcink dna skoob fo sevlehS
.erahs ot ton aedi na fo yzoc oot saw
,éfac eht hguorht pu detfaw snaeb gnitsaor fo llems ehT
,gnihtemos gnivarc era snogard rehto tsom kniht I“
deffins eod ehT
.erif fo psiw kciuq a htiw etalocohc toh sih no
,eert eht fo doow larutan eht morf edam erew sllaw dna sroolf ehT
.niamod reh fo esnapxe eht revo gnikool
,nohpyrg yhcuorg a saw eH
.kcab eht otni liat reh gnipool
tuo knuhc egral a gnipoocs ,maerc deppihw eht otni ti kcuts dna
,ffo devohs dna detnurg eh nehT
,daehrevo deraos yeroC
”?ereh yats neve uoy od yhW
”?okikuY thgir ,ot sah enoemoS“
.elims a htiw dias ehS
.sraey eht revo evissam os elpam eht edam tahw saw enola eeffoc eht fo tnecs eht taht dias emoS
rood eht yb gnittiS
”.wols fi neve ,ssergorp si ssergorP“
saw sihT.snaeb eeffoc
.noisicerp tfiws htiw devres dna deraperp lla erew sosserpse dna ,settal ,swerb ,soniccuppaC
”,yrtnuoc a gnidael ot serapmoc etiuq pohs eeffoc a erus ton m’I“
.thgil eulb thgirb a gnitingi
,deuqip saw noitnetta s’aralA
,kcab dekcilf srae s’okikuY .regnif s’okikuY ffo ti kcil ot drawrof denael flah rehto egnaro sih
.tekcub eht otni kcab pom sih gniknud erofeb wob lufyalp a evag imA
,aralA morf ssorca taes eht otni dils dna
”.ragus taht eganam uoy woh erus ton m’I
ylfeirb egap eht dennacs seye s’eod ehT
ew sseug I ,lleW“ .epolevne eht ta dekool eh sa desufnoc dna ediw seye ,deknilb nohpyrg ehT .sedemihcrA ot ti dednah dna epolevne dnoces a tuo dellup imA ”.oot detivni er’uoy ,esruoc fO“ .dias okikuY ”,llew sa noitativni tsrif eht er’uoY“
htiw ti hsats yeht os ,diov emos llif ot tnaw lla yeht
,yzoc dna mraw ,uoy htaeneb gnikab sdnas eht evah llits uoy
skoob eseht fo netaeb dna derettab tsom eht neve tuB
,erom ecno gniliar eht otno tpael eH .dias eH
,dias ehs ”,detros siht teg ll’eW .thgir lla s’ti ,hhS“
,flesmih reknird eeffoc a ton hguohT
.dereens aralA ”,lufwA“
.rof gnikool saw ehs egassap eht dnuof ehs litnu
”snaeB eeffoC detsaoR nogarD“
,emit emas eht tA
.gniog teg ot regae
.retnuoc eht no dehcrep erew swalc-erof sih os pu deppoh dna
.retnuoc eht ssorca namow namuh denniks-krad eht ot
ro sedart tnahcrem gninwo ekil
.noitativni eht ta tsol
”,ti devresed evah dluow eH“
.traeh dlo reh demraw
.txet lanigiro eht morf drow elgnis yreve dleh
”,eniledaM ssiM ,uoy knahT“
,gnuoy eb ot desu yehT
.gab reh otni seton s’ydneW pu dekcap eh sa delims okikuY
”!gib oot eb t’now ynomerec eht esimorp eW
.oga sraey ,seton ralimis revo gnidaer
.roputs gninrom rieht morf meht ekaw ot nageb snaeb detsaor fo tnecs yklis ,hcir eht sa ria eht deffins dna deralf sesoN
,lardehtac tneicna na gniretne era sretcarahc niam ehT“
ot era smret-dim tub-B“
reppoc fo ruf htiw
,sknaht ni deddon okikuY
emit a ta eerht meht gnikat
,elpuoc enustik a saw
.elims gniwonk a htiw deksa ehS ”?aralA ,llifeR“
.niaga pu tpews gnieb erofeb
.stekcop taoc sih hguorht degammur dna tekcub eht ni pom sih kcuts imA
.dnah eno ni dleh ehs
”,ecaps ruo esu ot gniog s’ehs fi gnihtemos rof gniyap eb dluohs ehS“
,sgnikram llams lareves erew ebolg eht nO
,sgniw sih fo palf a htiw yleritne sriats eht gnippiks
.pohs eeffoc elttil elpmis a morf lla ,eye s’dlihc a otni tup d’ehs rednow eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ecaf sih no elims gib a erow imA tub
,gniliar eht no pu deppoh saw yeroC
,aralA ,levon ruoy etirw oG“
,esu fo sedaced morf
”.taht gniredro enoyna llacer t’nod I“
,snaeb gnilooc eht hguorht swalc reh gnipoocs nageb dna
”?uoy dluow ,slleps laropmet no meroeht s’sulumoR dniheb sisab eht wonk ot neppah t’ndluow uoY“ .deggurhs ydneW
,yadot semit net egap eht ot lliuq ym tup ev’I“
.tca eht yb dessarrabme
.eod eht gnirussaer
ot sredaer eht teg
,llew sa revo emac ehS
swodniw eht hguorht demaerts nus nmutua psirC
.elbigel ssel ro erom saw ti tub
”?tib a rof ereh deyats I fi dnim uoy dluow
,noitom decitcarp a ni lwob eht dekcor tsirw reh
.tekcop norpa reh morf noops a gnippils ,dias eniledaM
,sdrawpu flesmih dehcnual ydaerla dah sedemihcrA
a eb lliw ti erus m’I
,nosinu ni tsomla
lardehtac eht fo thgim reehs tsuj dna ewa eht
.gniwolf kni eht tog netfo yeht tub
,sraet emos kcab deplug ydneW
.werb eht fo htaerb peed a gnikat
.teef reh ta gnicnad sevael rebma wef a
.elddup gnidliub eht pu pom ot gninnigeb dna
.eganrac eht revo gnikool
,pohs eht ,dworc eht ot tuo
...eciton tneiciffus nevig er’ew fi ,naem I
ydneW .enecs eht ees dluoc ehs litnu
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
”,meht gnitsaor yrt dluoc I“
.flehskoob reh ot revo edorts eniledaM ”…yllautcA“
,sriatspu dednecsa ehS
”!eutats a otni em deifirgomsnart ylraen eH
.taeh eht tuo neve ot ylwols meht gnitator
.steppins trohs noillim a ni hcae
,segareveb dna snoitasrevnoc rieht ot denruter snortap ynaM
,kcab dekcilf srae enustik fo stes htoB
.eciov reh sa teews sa dna ,niks reh sa krad sa hcae
lehctas sih morf shtolc fo elip a tuo gnillup ,roolf eht ot deppord neht seye sih dellor sedemihcrA
derutseg eniledaM ”,sihT
.kcab sih revo lehctas a ni decalp spuc fo elip a htiw denruter eh sa sedemihcrA deyE
,efac a ni tnemeticxe hcum os eb ot ereht tcepxe t’ndid I
.yart reh no ti decalp dna gum eeffoc ytpme eht pu dekcip nogard ehT
,citatsce saw ega fo sraey 7 ro 6 tuoba ebyam ,dlihc reH
”?won rof eciffo ym ni ti gnittup dna noitativni eht gnikat dnim uoy dluoW“
!krow ym revo eeffoc fo erahs ym llips t’ndid I fi retirw a eb yldrah d’I“
.elims citehtapmys a otni delruc htuom reH .dias eniledaM
snaeb eht fo ,ffhs ,ffhs ,ffhs eltneg ehT
.rof diap s’ti sa gnol os
”.srats gnilkniwt dnasuoht a htiw thgirb dna
”snaeB eeffoC detsaoR nogarD“
”,niarb drib ,hsuH“
.pihsnoitaler wen a fo sretaw eht gnitset
”,eniledaM ssiM ,erusaelp ruo s’ti
.egdelwonk reh tset ot snoitseuq dna seton htiw derevoc
”.em llet ot retnuoc eht ot pu gninnur emac ehs ti dnuof ehs nehw deticxe os saw ehS
,on yas ot nosaer doog a s’ereht kniht t’nod I
”.ereht tnew tsrif I nehw tneicna t’nerew yeht hguohtla
.deniur era seton ym
,tnemhcrap fo faehs reh ta gnirats saw aralA ,yadoT
,taeh nwo reh yb dezafnU
.wons gnihcnurc hguorht gnippets ekil hguor tub tfos eciov sih
”.erofeb dnim ruoy degnahc t’nsah ti tub
.delkcuhc okikuY .deksa eniledaM
,nalhguoC ”uorihS“ yaJ yb
.gum s’rohtua eht gnillifer erofeb reviled ot eeffoc a dah llits ehS
,mossolb pleh d’ehs egairram eht
,dam eb ot gniog ton s’ehS“
.eeffoc detcepxenu eht gnignirb rof flesreh ta yldrawni denworf ehS
”.raf os samolpid ym fo esu tseb eht neeb evah dluow tI“
.eye reh ni egdelwonk rof tsul a ,dias ehS
.naorg sedemihcrA gnikam ,decnuonna ehS
,sriats eht revo detserc htob okikuY dna imA ,taht dias eh sA
elddim eht ni ti denepo nogard ehT
”!deruonoh eb dluow eW“
”,retsaf ssecorp eht ekam ylniatrec dluow tI“
,ria eht otni nworht erew snaeb eht nehw
,elzzum sih otni ti gniffuts dna pot eht ffo maerc deppihw fo knuhc gib a gnipoocs ni emit elttil koot imA
.delbmurg sedemihcrA
,teef ruoy htaeneb yhsum tsomla ,tfoS
.dias
,reh dleh noitaripsni sa pis-dim
,em gnidnimer peek ot emoclew er’uoY“
.dluoc
”,lufituaeb sdnuos tahT“
tsehc s’eniledaM ni noisnet eht dna truh eb ot deraeppa eno on sa feiler saw ereht ,tnemom a roF
,yeroC ot txen gniliar eht ot denruter sedemihcrA sa srehtaef fo rettulf a saw erehT .delims aralA
.puc eht dnuora gnippoh
.oga sedaced tliub saw éfac siht nehw thgiarts dna ,psirc
.sliated esoht rof niarb ruoy gnikcip
,sknird ruoy yojne owt uoy ,lleW“
.sbos ylgu hguorht nwod reh gnimlac
,ni demihc okikuY
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”,eeffoc artxe taht ees I“
.dekniw eniledaM
.emoc d’uoy gnipoh erew ew dnA
.nwot ni revres tsetsaf eht eniledaM edam dah
troter ot emit evah t’ndid tub deggurhs eniledaM
.nevo na ni gnikab yllaitnesse er’uoy
.snoitseggus ro snoitadnemmocer gnikam dna ,esorp tsetal reh revo gnidaer
tneuqerf erom emaceb tub cidarops erew stisiv reH
,éfac eht ni dnuos fo ynohpocac eht otni delb
,meht deird ,knis eht ni sdnah reh dehsaw ot dehsur ehS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,gninrub ,toh osla s’tI
.scitna s’dneirfyob sih ta delims tub seye sih dellor okikuY
,elbat eht no eeffoc eht pu gnippos nageb dna sgar wef a pu koot eniledaM
,sreltna reh ni tas yeroC
.steknirt yldlrow eht revo dehsurb sdnah reh sa gnilims ,deton aralA
.seye dlo reh ni elkniwt a ,dias ehS
.secalp eseht ni yats dna tisiv ot teg yllautca ot gnizama eb tsum tI“
seton ruoy tuohtiw neve dna
.rae ot rae morf ediw dennirg aralA
.tahwemos dexaler
,ecnatsid eht ot dekool ydaerla seye reh tub ,deddon ydneW
.elims a htiw dias ehS
hT“ .teehs eht gnikat erofeb eson reh depiw dna
.edirp htiw dellews traeh reh dna
,ekila sremocwen dna sraluger htob ,snortaP
,seton eht fo eno pu dekcip aralA
éfac reh hguorht nar sevil dnasuoht A
,detfihs ro tneb reven dah yehT
,wonk t’nod I ...tsuj I“
.seton yrd won fo teehs dewolley a gnidloh saw ohw ,aralA ot denrut meht fo htob dna thgil eulb fo hsalf a saw erehT
,yas ot uoy rof-f ysae-E“ .dias eniledaM
,spil reh ot gum reh gnidloh eb dluow rehto eht
.tsef yduts siht rof rehtegot dellup selbat eht revo gnikool
.enod ev’uoy sgniht eht lla
.tseug eht teerg ot snoitaraperp gninrom reh morf denrut eniledaM yltnatsnI
.egakcerw eht gniees nopu depsag dna sriatspu eniledaM dewollof dah aralA ”.hO“
”,htob su etivni ot meht fo ecin si tI“
.skoob dna seton reh ta ylsselpleh gnirats
.rehtona ro tros eno fo rewop dna
,deye-yraelb ,esor daeh reH
.éfac eht ni koot seye ydaeb sih sa
.repap morf sdiuqil dellips evomer ot lleps a evah I
.ecarbme eht denruter dna
.sgalf evissam ekil deggaw sliat sih sa nirg yfoog ,ediw a otni tilps elzzum s’imA
,renwo eht taht dekoj dah sraluger s’pohs eht fo ynaM
.eznorb fo srehtaef dna
,daeh s’rentrap reh no walc eltneg a tup dna
,enituor eht ni tfiws dna decitcarp hcae
.sreksihw sih no gnihctac ffulf etihw eht fo spsiw
.rehtegot kcilc sgniht fo tol a edam tsuj ti dnuof ehs tub
”,retal sliated eht tuo krow ll’eW“
.snaeb eht tsaor ot erif-nogard reh desu eniledaM sa hctaw ot denrut dna
.serots reh gnillifer fo lautir reh nageb eniledaM
.srae sih neewteb gnikorts yltneg
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,eniledaM dellac nogard yarg mrots a
.thgir er’uoy tuB“ .dias aralA
,yawa llup ot deirt xof etihw eht ecno tub
,erehwyreve steg ti
”.taht tuoba od nac I hcum ton
,nalhguoC ”uorihS“ yaJ yb
,dnah ni poocs latem a htiW
.lufpleh yrev noitces siht dnuof rehtom ruoY“
om ,boj doog a teg t’now I ,ssap reven-
eniledaM ”,emit ynA“ ”.hcum yrev uoy knahT“ .seye reh ot gninruter saw thgiL .elims mraw a htiw dias ydneW ”,doog yllaer si ti ,hO“
,htaerb peed a ni koot ehs sa
.setunim wef a rof no tnew wohs ehT
reh dnuora yltneg smra sih tup tnemom a retfa tub
”.shtaerb peed emos ekat ot uoy deen tsuj I“ .dias eniledaM
.deddon eniledaM
skoobtxet dna srepaP
,secnamor dna seisatnaf dlo erew skoob eseht fo ynaM
.snoitasrevnoc rieht ot nruter dluoc yeht dna
.noitnevnoc lacol sih
,seohs rieht ni dnas eht ,skcab rieht no nus tresed toh
,elbidercni s’taht-
,thgir snoitome eht teg ot gniyrt tsuj m’I
tib a xaler ot demees ydob elohw reH .dias ydneW
,niatrecnu erew yehT
trecnoc ni desu neeb dah yrtneprac delliks dna cigam nevlE
,roolf dnoces siht no tas selbat nedoow eroM
detciped ylraelc retnec eht ni gnivargne eht tub
.hguone gnol ti ni er’uoy fi
”!daeh ruoy fo tuo gnitsrub slevon evah t’nod uoy desirprus m’I
,eerht uoy rof sdneirf fo elpuoc a thguorb I“
.lliuq reh deppid-er ehs dna
.knilc a htiw elbat eht no gum toh eht delttes dah eniledaM litnu tfihs t’ndid ydneW
.hcrep sih deltsoj dna tuoba devom
?desirprus llits I ma woH“
eerht eht gniwollof
”!gnipleh trats dna gnigguh pots syug uoy fi retsaf denaelc seton eseht teg ll’eW“ .dnah reh gnivaw
.noitasrevnoc rieht detpurretni sriatspu morf yrc delgnarts a dna
.reh revo gnimoc uv àjéd fo esnes a
,elpmaxe eht retfA
.elpmet reh no deniart deniamer sdnah reh dna evom t’ndid seye reh
,rufuocnaV rof dna skooB goD daB yb 7 RAOR
.lufhtuom sih hguorht dias imA ”,wols ooT“
.oga sraey ,tops yrev taht ta tem dah sdal ehT
.tnecs eht gniyojne
,gnippird deniamer koob eht ,revewoH
,gnitirw hctarcs nekcihc htiw drow hcae nwod delbbircs aralA
.noitatskrow reh nwod depiw ylkciuq dna yart a no lla meht decalp ehS
,egdelwonk dlo fo semot erew srehto tey
.worbeye reh gnisiar ,desaet eniledaM ”?yllaeR“
.yredarmoc eht ni gnithgiled
.aralA ot dias ehS
.dellac erew sredro eht erofeb tsomla sretnuoc eht morf dehctans erew stros lla fo seeffoC
,rehtegot spets railimaf rieht decnad yehT
.ylevitcepser egnaro dna etihw
denworf sedemihcrA
en ll’I-I“ .sbos ylgu neewteb htaerb reh gnihctac emit drah a gnivah saw ehS
.resolc reh gnillup
aet yojne ot keew yreve yb emac yeht woN
oga sraey elpuoc a slanif sih rof gniyduts saw eh nehW“
,wolley llits si teehs eht ,swen daB
.retnuoc tnorf eht naelc dna
.eeffoc fo arua erem eht yb detrela fi sa pu dekrep aralA
”?llew reh wonk uoy oD“
.elihwhtrow t’nsi ti gniyas m’I taht toN“ ,dias aralA
efac lacol a ni snaeb eeffoc nwo reh gnitsaor nogard a fo aedi eht
.dehcaorppa ehs sa dias ydneW
.smaerd dna epoh htiw no dleh segassap rieht ,senips kaew htiw
”,tuo pleh dluoc yeht ,yeson eb ot gniog erew yeht fi derugiF“
.seton reh ot denruter dnim reh sa noitseuq a gnitalpmetnoc
.sdnah regnig htiw egap eht pu dekcip ehs dna
,fle eht delbmuM ”.esaelp ,seY“
.snoitatnacni dna salumrof revo deruop ehs sa
.ynapmoc s’rehto hcae dna
.gnihctaw tpek sremotsuc rewen eht fo emos tub
,deretsulf sedemihcrA ”-naem I
,nees ev’uoy secalp eht llA“
,yad eht fo nortap tsrif eht ni detfird ria nmutua psirc fo tfard dloc A
.segap eht ssorca ssenkrad gnidaerps ,gnillips diuqil nworb
.delbmurg sedemihcrA
.ylsuovren kcilf ot demees sliat siH .dias eH
.knird eht ta derats ehs dna
.tniop eht gnissim er’yeht kniht I
.nirg rae-ot-rae na htiw dias eH
.pu worg nees d’ehs snoitareneg eht lla
”,taht rof noops a uoy gnirb did I“
.deen d’ehs lleps eht fo ezis eht rof pu ti gnieye
.devomer dah yeht doow elpam eht fo edam neeb lla dah sretnuoc dna ,sriahc ,selbat eht nevE
-dna egap a rof dehcaer I ereht
.suoiruc ,dekrep srae
”,ssem eht tuoba yrros ,sey ,hA“ ”.ylrae pu er’uoY“
.otni tliub saw éfac eht eert elpam evissam eht morf nwod detaolf sevael nosmirc dna dlog yzaL
”.deen uoy sa gnol sa yats ot emoclew er’uoy
.ecaf rieht ni dniw gnippihw a
”.tnatropmi llits tub
.tsael ta sedaced lareves yb detadtuo sessamdnal sti dna emit htiw dedaf saw ecafrus stI
.meht nwod dna pu gniklaw teef dnasuoht a morf nepahssim dna depraw
,doof ro knird a desahcrup ylerar ehS
!nogard a sa yllaicepsE
.ni emac fracs dlog-der dna tekcaj tlef kciht a ni eod gnuoy A
.yaws enitnepres yzal
”,kaerb hcnul ym no og ot gniog m’I
.erif dna eeffoc gnitsaor fo tnecs rettib ,mraw eht htiw kciht saw ria eht ,éfac eht edisnI
ygolohtna eht rof nettirw sah ohw
.denwo ew etalp yreve tsomla kaerb ot deganam dna erutinruf ruo fo lla degnarra-er I
wollamhsram eht tsaor eniledaM dehctaw eh nehw flesmih gnittew tsomla
,tops tcaxe siht ni tis ot desu ohw
.enola emoh yllacisab saw I
”,enoyreve rof ton s’tI“
.retnec eht morf emulov egral rehtar a dekculp dna
.nworf a htiw dias eH
.delggig hctiw gnuoy ehT
,scitilop ro scimonoce fo dlrow fo elur ot gnirreferP
”,uoy fo duorp eb llits lliw rehtom ruoy dna
.moor eht dezigrene swerb eht fo tnecs cirtcele
taeh fo tfardpu na no deirrac
.seye reh ni serihppas htiw ecaf cinocard a
,selor tnatropmi ni ereht tuo era ees uoy snogard tsoM
.dias ehS ”!gninrom doog ,ydneW“
.eson sih dellif tnecs eht sa denethgirb eH .dias imA
,etad fo tuo era sliated eht fo emoS
.elbat eht revo yldas pird ti gnittel
,ssem eht ta kcip ylsselpleh ot nageb ydneW
.tekcub pom eht otni gar dekaos reh gnippord
.elbat txen eht ot revo deklaw dna
,egap eht otni rulb dna edaf ot gninnigeb saw gnitirw eht dna ,ffits dna gniwolley erew segap ehT
.tfel yeht sa meht dniheb evaw ot denrut eh erofeb dias okikuY ”,pleh lliw taht smaxe eht rof spit emos tog ev’I“
,yad a seeffoc elpitlum deredro
.doow elpam naelc ,hserf fo edam
,ecaps fo hcni yreve dellif
”,tuo em swollem eh ,ikuY lla s’tI“
,shtaerb emos hguorht reh del yltfos eniledaM dna