"?daetsni newnorB yals uoy t'nod yhW
.g7erg( moc tod G-neves-E-R-G ta
.htirb arab eht rettub dna ecils ot drows ruoy desu I
"?yrneH riS ,ekuD eht htiw yadiloh no og yllaer ehs diD"
,erofeb renrehtuos a tem reven ev'I"
",ecivres aet suolevram a tahW"
,namretuL g7erG yb ”reyalsnogarD“
.eltsihw ot nageb elttek eht ,yltneserP ".thgir s'taht ,hO"
",em morf siht fo yna raeh t'ndid uoy ,lleW"
.”dlroW llamS“ levon sih rof raey tsal rojaM asrU eht now ohw
.tuo dlrow eritne eht enut tsuj nac I ,ysub teg I nehw tub
yrneH riS   # # #   .meht retfa dellac I
".ereh ydaerla era newnorB dna riaM
!taht tuoba dne on ot em sesaet riaM
nagromalG fo selat su dlot yrneH
.rosiv sih denepo dna
",ereh welf I erofeb pu ydit neve t'ndid I !on ssendoog ,hO"
.tae ot gnihtemos dah dna elbatrofmoc erew stseug ym erus gnikam
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,emutsoc hsival sih gniredisnoc
.delggig newnorB "!thgir er'uoY"
.hgual a gnimoob ,dias deneB
.evigrof esaelp ,hO"
",godamhtroP ni uoy yals ot drahciR riS tnes flesmih gnik eht taht dias yrneH riS"   .swalc egral reh ni revo nopaew etaciled eht gninrut ,dias newnorB
.gnidael saw eh erehw ees ot em rof detiaw dna denialpxe eh
.thgink a reven ylniatrec dna
"!em yals ot mih tnes sah gnik ehT
.trilf a hcus eb nac ehs ,reh sselb doG
.erutaerc gninnuts a si ehS
.htuos eht tuoba snoitseuq derettiwt dna
.taht teg em teL !noitarehtoB"
tnemom a rof derettuts yrneH   ".seod ydobyreve
.tnemom a ylno rof yrneH riS morf seye reh gnikat ,dias newnorB
"?mih ssim I did hO"
bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.elaV wbbE fo edistuo tsuj egalliv elttil a s'tI" .denialpxe ehs
.yrneH riS ,laicnivorp os su kniht tsum uoY"
,dias newnorB ",lla ta ffo hsad t'ntsum uoy ,on ,hO"
.erofeb skrow rieht fo yna nees yllautca reven ev'I tub
.pu snesool eh ecno relletyrots lufrednow a si yllaer eH
.ytluciffid elttil dah yrneH
.nwonk dah I hsiw ylno I"
.yrneH riS teem tsum uoY .ereh emoc ,riaM"
.pu dekool eh nehw deneB deksa I "?owt ro pmul enO"   ".em
.draeh dah ew sromur suoladnacs eht fo emos mrifnoc eh did deirp riaM nehw ylno tub ,truoc fo dna
,nonyB htynewG eman yM"
,riaM si siht yrneH riS .yrneH riS si siht ,dyolL riaM"
.elims a htiw dezigolopa I
.yhs eb ot mih desseug I dna
".no kcab elttek eht tup em teL
ereh flesym dna ,elaV wbbE ot ruhtrA riS
.addnohR eht morf ni welf tsuj I tub ,dum-eht-ni-kcits a ekil dnuos ot tnaw t'nod I" .dehgis riaM
,godamhtroP ot drahciR riS" .deunitnoc eh
.ti wenk I !htuos ehT"   "...nagromalG
,dias ehs "?dnim uoy dluoW"
.ehcatsum yddur a dna seye neerg ,emosdnah dah eH
.tuo yaw sih no swalc s'newnorB fo kcab eht dessik neve eH
t'nevah I"
.swalc reh htiw ecaf reh gnirevoc ,delggig newnorB
.dnah sih morf ti gnikat
.emit tsegnol eht rof riaM ta derats yrneH
,steltnuag dna mleh sih ffo koot eH
,yrneH riS ,dnim t'nod uoy epoh I"
".yb deppop nagromalG
.yenruoj gniticxe na dah evah tsum uoY"
.elbatrofmocnu elttil a ylno gnikool ,elbat eht ta yletilop tas
",t'ndluoc I .on ,hO"
".tey htuos raf os neeb t'nevah ew tub ,meht tuoba lla draeh ev'eW" .deggeb newnorB
",egroeG riS neeb evah tsum tahT"
",yrneH riS teem dna ereh emoc ,newnorB"
".etal os si eh yhw nialpxe dluow tahT
.eunitnoc ot mih rof detiaw dna
",reyalp ssehc lufrednow a s'eH"   .deksa riaM
desufnoc saw I taht was eh nehW
"?ti dnif uoy did reverehW" .dedda eh
etisbew sih morf yltcerid skoob sih rof pohs ot enoyreve sksa won eh ,ycips oot gnieb rof acitore sih dennab yeht retfa tub
.yrros ylbirret os m'I ,hO ?nogarD"
,kced egral eht etipseD
.htuom ym revo swalc ym tup dna
snoitcerid tnereffid derdnuh a ni gninnur saw dna liob ot elttek eht tes tsuj dah I
".nogard a yals ot emoc ev'I .seirots llet ot ereh emoc
.uoy dnim ,dneirf tseb ym fo suolaej m'I taht toN
.wonk ton od ylniatrec I ,nrevac ym ot dael taht srebmahc eht hguorht gniknalc yrneH riS ssim ot deganam I woH   namretuL g7erG yb ”reyalsnogarD“:yojne esaelP
.swalc ym deppans I
.ysor werg skeehc s'yrneH
,newG em llac yam uoy tub
tsiaw eht ni mils si ehS
,mra s'thgink eht ta deggut dna dehsulb newnorB
".evah I taht yas t'nac I"
.thgil eht ot ti dleh dna resolc ti thguorb riaM
detniap saw etalp tsaerb sih dna reppoc htiw demmirt erew segde ehT
,snasitra nagromalG eht tuoba draeh syawla ev'eW
.noitanicsaf tpar ni tas ew dna
".emag egdirb ylkeew ruo nigeb dluoc ew os deneB rof gnitiaw tsuj erew eW"
".lla retfa ,stseug ylno er'eW
",drows sih ees tsum uoy dna ,seY"
.em htiw elbat eht denaelc eh llits dna level ym ot nwod gniyalp saw eh llet dluoc I"
.ereh tsuj saw ,yrneH riS ,dneirf siH" .dias I
seye ym dettab I ".yrneH
"?yrneH riS ,riaM yals uoy t'nod yhW
"?yrneH riS ,esaelp ,seltsac nagromalG eht fo su lleT"   .tlaed yrneH dna tuc riaM .dnah hcae htiw sdrac eht derehtaef dna swoble sih htiw skcats eht dleh eH
.gnildeehw sseltneler reh ot dedecnoc yllanif yrneH dna ,newnorB htiw secalp degnahcxe I   ".lliw uoy yas esaelP
.detsuahxe etiuq ma yllaer I
.llew sa tseuq a no gnieb sthgink rehto eht tuoba gnihtemos noitnem did eH"
"?rehtaf reh eb ot hguone dlo ekuD eht t'nsi tuB"
dehsulb yrneH   .delggig newnorB
.enidneP tfel eh erofeb deneB htiw pu thguac evah tsum egroeG riS"
,esirprus a etiuq saw tI
...nellognalL ot
.resolc reh devaw I dna renroc eht dnuora dekeep riaM
"?gniht a hcus fo draeh reve uoy evaH"
.gnissarrabme yrev woH"
.em esirprus yllaer ton did ti os
”reyalsnogarD“ saw sihT
.flesym rehtegot egairrac eht ni teg meht was I"   .deksa riaM
,nozamA no pu slevon lareves sah g7erG
.demialcxe I ",gnimit etanutrofnu tahw ,hO"   ".uoy yals ot
.moor gninid eht ot kcab mih dael ot gniyrt
",lufituaeb era sehciwdnas rebmucuc eseht dnA"
.llaw eht no txet derediorbme "...ton
.noitcudortni na htiw revo detrats dna ystruc tseb ym mih evag I
.sllacer eh erofeb nagromalG ot kcab yaw eht lla teg t'nseod eh epoh od I
"?ti dnif uoy did reverehW" .dias riaM
",neht kcab emoc ot evah tsuj lliw eh esoppus I ,lleW
.traeh ym ot walc a tup dna depsag I "!ssendoog ,hO"
",ecivres aet ylevol a tahW !hO .esaelp ,enO"
.sniatnuom eht ni garc ylevol a sah newnorB"
,nialpxe I yrneH
.thgir eb t'ndluow tsuj ti ,sediseB"
.sehsid eht pu gnitcelloc ,dias I
.kcalb tej era sgniw ediw reh dna
"?krow eriw etacirtni eht ees uoy diD !eldnah siht dnA"
.skeehc deroloc laocrahc reh ot swalc reh gnippalc ,dias newnorB
"?esaelp ,ti tuoba su lleT
dah mleh depahs daeh lakcaj siH
peed a era selacs reH
yawa mih dael newnorB
"?ekil egroeG riS si tahw oS"
.derettit newnorB
".tsen reh morf aes eht ees nac uoY
...ton tlahs uohT" eht dna ,stseug rehto ym
.depsag ehs "!drows ylevol a tahW"
nehw evael ot ydaer gnitteg tsuj saw I" .dias eh ",yrros yllufdaerd m'I"   ".ti ekam ton dluow uoy diarfa erew eW" .thgit mih dezeeuqs dna deraor riaM "!deneB"   .nrevac ym deretne eh sa dellac deneB "!etal m'I yrros oS"   ".ti
elap tib a dekool noixelpmoc siH
.noitarehtob hO"   .em dednimer
.sil-ed-ruelf neerg tserof a htiw
,yaw taht erew srenrehtuos taht draeh dah I
.ti fo draeh ev'I emit tsrif eht s'tI .ynomerec nainagromalG fo tros emos saw ti demussa I .aedi tsetniaf eht t'nevah I" .daeh ym koohs I dna deggurhs riaM   .ymaerd tahwemos eciov reh ,deksa newnorB "?rednow I ,eb 'gniyals' dluow tahw woN"
,enidneP ot egroeG riS
.god.ecioveht ta
.htims tsenif s'nagromalG yb edam neeb
.elffuhs ot dedeecorp dna
".yrneH em llac esaelp od dnA
riaM "!uoy yals ot
,did eh nehw dna ,tnemom a rof gnihton dias yrneH
oT ".sroolf ruoy ffo tae ylbaborp dluoc uoy ,uoy wonk I fI .hsiP"   ".gnissarrabme
.yrneH riS ,uoy rof od I nac revetahW
"?yrneH ris ,aet ruoy ni nomel ro kliM"
.gnitpurretni pleh ton dluoc I taht deticxe os saw I ".ti
.dias ehs "!romra ylevol tahw ,yhW ?yrneH riS"   .dellac I
"!nogard ,uoy yals ot emoc evah I"
",dnal eht fo srenroc eht ot sthgink tsevarb ruof sih tnes sah gnik ehT"
".elaV wbbE fo nogarD eht
"?ti ekil uoy od ,hO"
.tniap tew ekil maelg yeht thgilnus eht ni dna der ybur
.mih emalb yllaer t'nac I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,htolcelbat demmirt-ecal eht neewteb yllanoisacco detrad seye siH
.deganam eh ",ma'am ,seY"
.dnah sih revo swalc reh gnittup ylsselemahs
si yrots s’yadot dna
wolley thgirb dehsulb I ".thgink
",tra fo krow laer a si sihT"   .dedda riaM
"?yrneH riS ,ti t'nsaw ,drahciR riS saw tI" .reh dlot I
)g7erg/moc.noertap( G-neves-E-R-G hsals moc.noertap ta noertaP sih hguorht mih troppus ot ro )moc.g7erg(
.lamrof ylbirret os dednuos eh
morf nam gnuoy ecin a
.tseug remrof ruo rof dnuora gnikool ,dias deneB
"?yadot srennam ym era erehW
.daetsni rentrap ym eb tsum uoy ,yrneH riS ,hO"
,lavinrac fo su dlot eH
.niaga elap dekool eH ".htirb
".ti tuohtiw evael dna ffo hsad t'ntsum uoy ,woN .knis eht ediseb kcar gniyrd eht ni ti tup dna ti dehsaw I"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.gnilims pleh t'ndluoc I
,)seitrap ta yaw ym si sa(
.ecafrus rorrim a ot dehsilop neeb dah taht romra fo tius ylevol a ni eot ot daeh morf desserd saw eH
",olgnytnaN morf m'I ,yllautcA"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,namretuL g7erG yb
".em rof tsuj meht derif egalliv eht ni nwod nagroM .srM"
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
".kcohs a hcus em evag uoY"
.daeherof ym deppals I ".erofeb
.nagromalG ot kcab dedaeh dna raeg sih detcelloc yrneH ,revo saw emag eht nehW   # # #   .dedda eh
togrof eH"   .sevlesruo ot rethgual ruo tpek I dna riaM
"?yrneH riS ,aet retfa em yals uoy t'nod yhW .llew yrev ,hO"
".gniffips yletulosba si tI ?drows siht no pihsnamkrow eht ees uoy did ,raed ,newG"
.nagromalG fo dnal eht fo yrneH riS ma I"
.thguoht eh sa rae sih dniheb selacs neerg thgirb eht dehctarcs deneB
.edaps hgih a dehguols dna
.eerga ot dah I ",deedni ,sey hO"
".tnewG ni reve era uoy fi tisiv dna emoc tsum yllaer uoY
",newG gniyals tuoba gnihtemos dias yrneH"   ".llew