.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
esirhgiH redips eht fO
,tcefrep a syojne eH
renroc kraD eno ni ytefas debbeW
”II redipS knurD“ saw sihT      .tliug ym fo
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,gniroda eno hcaE
skoob aitnepreS eht fo rohtua eht si ehS
nerdlihc yhtlaeh dnasuoht a dnA
aipotu dinhcarA knurd tsop
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.sretcarahc lamina htiw seirots citnamor dna evitaluceps setirw ohw
mih tae oT seirt reven tsomla ohw efiw taf a sah eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,seires noitaN dirbyH dna
floWcaM boR si sihT
,iluaP secnarF yb
,iluaP secnarF yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
,relevart wollef ruoy
knarD tsomla I taht redips ehT
tnemtrapa esuohtnep sih nI
,”II redipS knurD“   yojne esaelP
iluaP secnarF yb meop a
.stroffe yliad sih roF lufetarg
.sniatruc ym evobA
.etisbew reh no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
sgniht retteb ot no tneW