…eritne …eht taefed nac uoY !tseb eht er’uoY !syug ,yrrow t’noD“ .gnas dna
?thgir ,ecitcarp s’ti
.mih dniheb pu gnirebmul nogard gninnirg a htiw
.gnorts saw gniwyerG
,taerht yna ecaf dluoc yeht erus tlef eh
.sredips eht raen tam elttab eht no
.taht morf zer nac uoy kniht neve t’nod I
edis ruoy no mih ekil enoemos evah ot doog os tlef ti
”!ruasonid ssuw elttil ynit a saw ti dias uoY“
.eb dluow rebbatspmuhC fo noisrev naem a tahw
”!oN“ .ecid eht ta ylsselesu detuohs eh ”!oN“
.yats rieht revoc ot hguone naht erom saw hcihw—
,hguone tnedifnoc saw eH
”.ytiretxed dna htgnerts ruoy evorpmi dna roivaheb kcap nrael uoy woh ees nac I ,erus rof ,stropS
”—og uoy erofeb ,drofliM riS“
,suomrone saw mih revo gnidnats tsaeb ehT
.etals fo bals evissam a ssorca deggard gnieb krof tnaig a ekil eciov sti
.etul sih gnulsnu dah dna
.egaruoc sih neeb dah gniwyerG
rettiwt no mih wolloF
gniworruf sekips ynroh ,deggaj eht
.esuoh eht no erew sknird ruoy :drab
.enif adnik ’nikool er’uoy ,yddub ,ereht yeH“
.nrevat yreve ta siht did drofliM riS
.ssarg eht drawot ti dekcilf dna repap fo daw llams a til llong eht ,xob rednit reh ot kcilf tfed a htiW
.sredips tnaig yb dednuorrus
?siht no ni tnaw uoy—
.yad eht fo dne eht yb ffo raew dluohs tI“
.ti morf gnitaidar taeh eht edih dluoc eh hguoht sa
.hcamots s’belaC ni dettonk raeF ?rennid dnA
ydissaC aiv drofliM riS morf gnos utpmorpmi na dna ytinmelos taerg htiw ,dna
.mih dniheb morf emac lworg wol A .htaerb saw tI
swalc sih htiw smurts wef a ti evag eH
.rab eht ta gnittis dlobok elttil mils a ot yltcerid gnignis
.klat etam eht htiw elbatrofmoc yltcaxe t’nsaw eH ”…yak …hO“
.nailitper ,deot-eerht ,suomrone
,nethgirb ot demees nrevat ehT
,nogard eht drawot denrut eH
.nageb eh ”—fliM riS“
,erus tnecrep derdnuh eno ton m’I“
.denworf drab ehT .deksa eh
.purys elpam toh ni gninword saw niarb sih ekil tlef tI ”…I dna uoY“
”.lla s’taht ,semitemos ylsuoires erom elttil a sgniht ekat d’uoy hsiw tsuj I“
.erew uoy taerg woh tuoba gnos rieht retfa thgir edulcni ot dah
hguoht sa t’nsaw tI .htrae fo slevohs wef a htiw ni ti dellif neruaL sa
.yaw taht belaC fo kniht reven dluoc eh taht yas dna kool gniytip
lufwa saw gnimit ehT
.ytnewt larutan a dellor dah retsnom ehT
.eveileb-ekam tsuj saw tI
.nihc reh ta debbur ehS ”.sseug I ,fo dniK“
.efas s’taht yaw a ni tluda na sa od ot tog ev’uoy ffuts eht lla od ot woh gninrael er’uoY
.hself sih hguorht ssenbmun dloc a gnidnes dna
.emag eht ni degagne
.deciton gniwyerG ,teiuq saw tI
erehT“ ”.yrros os ma I .belaC ,hsog ym hO“
”.uoy knaht on ,naem I .oN“
,srehtaef sih delffur ti fo dniw ehT
.srehtaef sih hguorht gninnur avilas dna doolb
.retal sruoh ruof tuoba ffo erow yllanif monev ehT
ruf eninoel sih gnitartenep sgnaf sti
neeb d’eh erehw tsuj doots nohpyrg citsalp elttil s’belaC
decitcarp d’eh gnihtyreve tuB
.dekcatta eb ot ylekil t’nerew yeht ereh tsael ta tub
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,niap ni deraor tI
,enot evissimsid reh etipseD
.wenk eh ,ti deen t’ndid eH
,noos nwod nael dluow tI
.net eb dluow amsirahc ym ,teehs retcarahc a dah I fI .ma I ohw wonk I
tog eM“ .gel sih ta nwod dekool gniwyerG ?tiB
.nohpyrg eht sa diarfanu dna tnedifnoc sa eb dluoc eh dehsiw eH
,elbat eht ta tas ydissaC
tnemegaruocne emos dedeen meht fo owt eht dediced yltnerappa dah drofliM riS
,dnik a mih evig dluoc eH
.meht fo yna dne dluoc etib elgnis A
,gnos fo tfig ym hguorht uoy niatsus lliw I“
teerts eht nwod gnieelf og ot ydaer tuoba tlef hcamots siH
”…su gnipleh uoy tuohtiw ,yeH“
.yug eht ton ,sey gniyas ela eht eb d’ti tub
,murts a ti evag dna redluohs sih morf etul sih gnulsnu ylismulc eH
”?huh ,strahc eht fo pot eht ot gniog s’eno taht ,woW“
.revognah a htiw retteb thgif I“
”.reipmiw dna rellams tub ,xer-t a ekiL
.erofeb thgin eht meht ot tuo detniop dah sregalliv eht htap trid a gniwollof erew yehT
,retcarahc eht nwonk yllaer t’ndah eh ,snoisses wef tsrif siH
,tih dilos a ,tih doog a saw tI
.raef eldnah ot woh wenk eh tuB
.orb a fo dnik gnieb dna reeb dna llabtoof gnivol osla etipsed
# .emit emas eht ta gnikaerb senob sih fo eno elgnis yreve fo dnuos eht saw draeh eh gniht tsal ehT
.yldrazahpah detuorps dah sekips dna snroh ynam hcihw hguorht romra ynob htiw dereyal
”,su htiw nogard lautca na evah ew nehw serif gnithgil eno eht eb ot evah syawla I yhw onnud I“ .parC
semalf htiw dellif saw ria eht neht dna
,eno siht sa elitsoh sa dlrow a nI
.swap sih ni ecid sih dehcnelc belaC ”!neruaL
detuohs eh ”!yks eht otni pu dehcnual redips ystib-ysti ehT“
.niaga ruodnelpS s’elgaE rof lleps eht derettum dna yawa denrut eH
.gnikoj ydaerla erew yehT
.dennirg dna ,ti dekrocnu ,kcap reh morf ksalf ssalg ,dnuor a dellup ,llong eht ,rebbatspmuhC
.erats nailitper ,denrecnoc a htiw nosyerG dexif drofliM riS
.gnillaf saw eh nehT
.nekorb dna detsiwt erew sehcnarb eht ,pu hgiH
,won tsuj ylbakil yrev devaheb t’ndah eH
.ti ta doog saw eh dnA
,llabtoof a ekil yawa delias gniht eht sa
.deppans etul sih no gnirts a dna
drow thgir eht yltcaxe saw deretsalp ,tcaf nI
.rood oitap eht denepo eH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.llik ot sredips dah yehT
.edisni dekool dna oitap s’repinuJ fo rood ssalg eht ot pu deklaw eH
htap s’euqsallam eht fo tuo dellor gniwyerG
,enut fo tuo tib a neeb evah tsum etul siH
”…I dna uoy yas uoy od tahW !yfliM ,ereht yaS“
”,thgir uoy sevreS“
”?semag tuoba ekil I tahw wonk uoy ,yeH“
.kaeb sih nwod gnidils loord
.wohemos ,laer erom tlef dah nohpyrg eht gnieB
.daeh sih detlit drofliM riS
,redluohs dna mra sih gnicreip niap
ytilibapac dna ecnedifnoc fo egrus lausu eht leef t’ndid gniwyerG esuaceb
redluohs sih otni knas
.dnuorg eht ffo mih dellup dna
.dnuorg eht gnola deggard ylraen
.ria eht ni dezzub stcesni oN
.ytilanosrep emas eht hcum ytterp htiw llong a deyalp ehs taht pleh t’ndid ti dna
egnul neddus a woleb gnikcud neht dna
”?laer ton er’yeht tahT“
,esolc sihT .swaj deksut
.delbmurg rebbatspmuhC
,deid dah laer enoyna
sseddog a ton m’I .MG eht ylno m’I ,yeH“
?uoy htiw gnorw s’tahW“
.stats efil-laer sih lla htiw eno eht
,si tniop eht ,kooL“
.uoy ot tnatropmi saw taht wonk I“
”?yako ,worromot klat ll’eW“
”.tnuh gib a erofeb thgin eht hcum os gniknirD“ .deppans gniwyerG
.emit tsrif ym s’ti ,yeh esuaC‘ ?netfo ereh emoc uoy oD
,hgiht renni sti—
,daeh sih revo depmalc wollip eht htiw moor nwo sih ni yal gniwyerG ,thgin tahT
,sey a teg thgim uoy ,eruS
.smurdrae desserts-revognah sih gnicreip
.mih ta gnirats ,tnemom a rof tsol tog gniwyerG
llong a fo erugif ekil-aneyh eht decalp repinuJ
.og raef sih tel dna
”?dnuora dlog siht lla gniyrrac gniod sredips era tahW“
ti s’woH“ .nogard eht ,drofliM riS fo erugif elttil eht revo gnikconk ylraen
,llebpmaC nayR yb
.seert eht otni pu derats gniwyerG
.hself sih gnissim tsuj dna srehtaef sih hguorht
.ssarg eht hguorht liart eht no edis ot edis morf dehcrul eH ”!hcamots ym dnA
eloh eht otni derats belaC
,siht htiw nar I fi em dlot syawla mom yM“
,swaj s’gniht eht morf htrof dna kcab gnuws gniwyerG
,deraeppa rebbatspmuhC
.serehw wonk t’nod yllaer I tub smoordeb sah ecalp siht wonk I
.kniht I ,emas eht era semaG
”.ti wonk uoy dna ,semag ruo ot ssalc sdda tI“
.elbat eht tih ecid eerhT .dias repinuJ
.aera dedoow a fo edahs eht otni dna sdleif eht fo tuo meht del htap ehT
,mih ta depag gniwyerG
.tnemom tcefrep a saw tI .ffo deliart eh
.gnitrilF .gnignis toN .oN
,drofliM riS ot revo edorts eH
seton yekffo fo dnuos eht ta lluks sih tsniaga gninettalf snif rae sih ,decniw tub
”,gnits yam“ htiw ”gniwyerG“
.erif eht ni gnilzzis sredips tnaig fo spop tew dna gnissih eht dna
”!gel ni seloh adiops
”.ereh steg ssaC sa noos sa tsuJ .os kniht I“
.ydaer eht ta eb dluow drows nwo sih ,did ti nehw dna ,eerf eye sti ni drows eht eparcs ot gniyrt
.txen semoc tahw tuo erugif ll’ew dna net ekat lla s’teL
.gnorw saw gnihtemoS .deretlaf eH
.kcab eht no tap a mih evag repinuJ
”?uoy did ,tib teg t’ndid uoY .orb ,on hO .on hO ?huH“
.siht rof tnemom elbirret a saw tI
,nrevat eht ssorca gniyahsas saw drofliM riS .deknilb eH
nirg lufeur a uobirac eht evag ydissaC
,raelc yllanif saw dnim siH .thguoht eh ,woN
,ecaf sih ssorca gnipeerc morf elims gniroda ,diputs eht pots ot deirt belaC
.raef ot snosaer fo stol erew erehT
eguh saw ti ,saw ti revetahW
ruodnelpS s’elgaE rof noitatnacni eht derettum eH
.dnah eno htiw sreltna gniddub reh ta dehctarcs ehS
,elttab eht retfa sa tnemom a tcefrep sa t’nsaw tI
.edisni daeh reh dehctaw belaC
,stnirptoof deot-eerht ,evissam fo stnanmer eht tuo ekam llits dluoc gniwyerG tub
.delggig repinuJ ”,oh oh oh hO“ .noruaS fo
.decitcarp d’eH .denrael d’eh dna ,deyalp d’eH .elttil a
.selpmet sih debbur gniwyerG
.edud ym ,raey yrevE“
thginot nrevat lacol eht ta sgnos eht wenk yeht dna
.ssarg eht ni ffo ecam sih depiw gniwyerG ”!saw ti ,haeY“
,yrev saw drofliM riS—
.yaced dna doolb fo knats htaerb stI
.elpoep ot klat ot uoy rof ysae s’tI“ .dehgis belaC
.tuo mih ksa ot tnaw tsuj I“
.thgilnus eht morf seye sih dedleihs dna denaorg drofliM riS   ”.ooh ooh hoO“
.ti revo teg tsuj dluohs I dnA
…evah tsum uoy ,tacbob a er’uoY
.detuohs drofliM riS ”!parc ,hO“
noitnevnoc delzzufnoC eht rof nettirw yllanigiro
.noitatirri reehs fo tuo uoy fo tol eht llik annog ylbaborp m’I os
liat s’euqsallam eht otno tpael rebbatspmuhC
.maet a er’ew taht tsuj s’ti …tsuj s’tI“
?ti ecnahc yhw tuB .hguone gnimrahc
.doolb der krad s’gniht eht htiw gnippird sedalb reh
.stacbob tsuj ton ,ffuts taht seod dik yrevE .sseug I ,haeY“
.riahc eht fo kcab eht hguorht liat sih gnidaerht
.dub ,neht litnu uoy retfa kool ll’eW
.nwod srood owt selitper citsaisuhtne fo sdnuos duol eht elffum ot gniyrt
”.thgif ot deraperp ereh emac ew rof ,thgilf ekat llew sa thgim retsnom sihT .raer eht ni euqsallam eht debbats rebbatspmuhC roF“ ,gnus eh ”,raef ton seod ytrap ruO“
.gnillaf ylraen dna spets wef a nwod gnilbmuts ,dehcrul eH
,mih ta degnul sredips ybraen eht fo eno ,nar eh sa tub
.ti tuoba kniht ot ton drah os gniyrt saw eH
,kcab sih no sgniw elgae eguh fo htgnerts dna thgiew eht ,tnemom a rof ,tlef eH
.ti ta pu deworc gniwyerG ”!uoy tog eW !aH“
.neercs MG reh gnidlofnu ,elbat eht fo dne ta doots repinuJ ”.tac ,yeH“
.esruoc fo ,tsrif ta yaw taht neeb t’ndah tI
,gnippird sti fo
!rebbatspmuhC ,ynnuf ton s’tI“
.erofeb stats sih lla tuo dekrow d’eh esuaceb dnah no tats taht dah eH ”.ebyam ,nevelE
”!noitanigami ym …ni rellams dekool tI !yrros m’I“
.01 noitutitsnoc
,reh hctac ot gniyrt ,tuoba degnul retsnom eht sa sehcnarb eert gnigdod ,daeh sti ot pu yaw eht lla nar ehS
,tcepser fo yhtrow dna
”?huh ,ni gnimoc sreltnA“
”?ynit llac uoy tahw si sihT
,driew saw tnemom eht dna
.hcum os uoy ekil I .lla dna yrteop daB
:dezilaer eh ,etal oot tnemom a dnA
,redluohs sih no llef dnah ytaem s’ydissaC
”.tnirptoof a er’uoY .aH“
.daerpsdeb tew a ekil
”?taht s’kceh eht tahW“
.hguorht kaeps dluoc eh eciov A .odavarb siH
,on tub—llaf ot tuoba saw ti thguoht gniwyerG tnemom a rof dna ,edis eno ot dehcrul tI
.mih llif ecarg enivid tlef dna
”,sgub bmud uoy ,siht no ekohC“
.rebbatspmuhC dereens
.gnitalumits neeb yltcaxe t’ndah noitasrevnoc eht tub
”?siht ekil thgif neve uoy naC
;teef sih no dnal dna tsiwt ot emit t’nsaw erehT
.spil sti neve dna
.retcarahc sih no daetsni desucof dna
.ecalp dab a saw sihT
”?em llet ot gniyrt erew uoy ti saw tahW .oS
.kaerb a deen ew kniht I“
”!sredips er’yehT ?no ti dneps ot gniog yeht era tahW“ .deggurhs repinuJ
.modgniK denworD eht fo aoK dna
”?yako ,tnemom doog a mih evig tsuJ
.reisae emoceb dah ti dna
.ta gnitteg saw ehs tahw was eH .bmud t’nsaw eH
”?ti thgif ot od ew dluohs tahw ,oS“
.tae oT .tacbob tluda na sA .yerp
,ylduol dehcleb neht ,pu-sbmuht a mih evag nogard ehT ”.orb ,erus roF“
”.revetahw dna ,etam a dnif dna ,evivrus ot ffuts od dnA
.tuo emoc t’nseod ti fo tsom ,klat I nehw dnA .traeh ym ni dna—dna daeh ym ni hcum os s’ereht …em tuB
”!duol oS !duol oS !hggA“
”.uoy sllet egdelwonk cidrab ruoy
.elbat eht no nwod eeffoc detanobrac fo retil a deknuht dna
,selur eht fo gnikcehc hsirevef fo tol a saw txen emac tahW
.si gniwyerG tuB“ .dias eh ”,ton m’I“
.dab yreV .dab saw sihT
,mih fo daeha owt eht ot dellac eh ”?syuG“
.srae sih denettalf belaC
,raef taht ta deddon yllatnem belaC
smug hguorht yldrazahpah tsurht
.mih denethgirf gnihtoN
,sgel yldnips ,gnol no gniwyerG dnuora derettiks sredips kcalb dna wolley ylkcis ehT
.rewsna ni murts lacismihw a evag drofliM riS
,yamsid teiuq fo stnemom wef a yb dewollof
,mih woleb gnikcor dnuorg eht
”?huh ,em evah syug uoy ykcuL“
,emit elohw eht ereht neeb d’ehs hguoht sa
,edis ot edis morf gnihcrul
.stoob s’gniwyerG sa llew sa
.wehpen dlo-raey-ruof s’legna taht yb nettirw sciryl dna
,doof fo sreniatnoc gnimaets denepo dna
htaerb peed a koot eH
"ruodnelpS s’elgaE" saw sihT
.yek gninut eht htiw
.hcaer ot gnipael
.mih dniheb yrrow dna raef sih gnivael
.deirrow t’nsaw belaC
”.gniht regnad eht tuoba wonk ot uoy stnaw egdelwonk cidrab ym“
”?diova ot yrt dluohs ew gnihtyna ,stops kaew ynA“ .deksa eh
.tser lanif sti ot teehs retcarahc s’gniwyerG dial yeht—
.smra sih dedlof belaC
.skcor eht ssorca rohci dinhcara derettalps dna
.htraeh nrevat eht dnuora detalumucca dah taht sdraknat fo yarra evisserpmi eht deciton won ylno gniwyerG .knurd yrev
.ereht ni drows sih teg ot elba eb thgim eH
.elbat eht ta derats belaC
,seenk sih ot pord drofliM riS edam taht
,ekiL .oot ffuts gnitnuh lla s’ti tub ,thgiR“ ”.stacbob
,daehrevo drows sih gnidloH
.eye sti otni drows reh knus ehs dna
,21 ytiretxed ,9 htgnertS
,oot ,lleh ekil sehctI
”?gniht siht od ot ydaer eW ?sklof ,’niog
,dlog ytnewt tuoba gniyrrac neeb dah sredips ehT
.seirots detcelloc ohw yug eht eb dluow ti
.sriatspu dlobok eht dewollof eH
.ti dessap deppets eh nehT
”?haeY .gniht laer eht rof ydaer uoy teg pleh oT
”.sessadab er’ew esuaceB“
,ecalp tsrif eht ni gnimag otni belaC nettog dah ohw eno eht saw eh dna ,yppah ,tfos ,gib saw eH
.ereht saw ti taht gnigdelwonkca
.rehtona sa ylisae sa dehsauqs redips tnaig enO
,ralugerri dna deggaj werg hteet sti taht ees dluoc eh
.elbarenluv erew seenk sti fo skcab eht ,oS
.dias drofliM riS ”,yddub elttil ,yrrow t’noD“
mih no nwod gnisserp yamsid yvaeh a tlef belaC tub
.nerdlihc gnissim fo elpuoc a rof elbisnopser neve saw
pmuht a htiw dnuorg eht tih eh
eert nommisrep reh ot txen eloh elttil a gud yehT
denrut eH .gnilialf sgel
.thgilnus thgirb eht fo tuo eb ot dalg dekool drofliM riS
selcabed laciryl rehto htiw gnola
”.ti ees t’nod uoY“
.liat reh deggaw rebbatspmuhC
,dnuora denrut nogard ehT
.devol yeht sgniht eht gniod deyojne dna elpoep dekil ohw yug yldneirf a tsuj saw eH
,emit lanif eno ynoga ni dewolleb euqsallam ehT ”!mom ,sknahT
.elbat eht ssorca gnicnuob 02d a tnes dna
.gnipmil ydaerla saw ti dna
,ssarg dekaos-lio eht fo tuo dehsad dna
,redluohs delaeh ylerab sih ta debbur eH
.ti tsap devom uoY
llebpmaC nayR yb
a gnieb fo egatnavda ehT
.ti tuoba yrrow t’noD
”.mudmud ,gniog eciN“
…tnuh og ot evah d’uoy
,denrael d’eh ,hguoht ,niks s’gniwyerG ni dnuora gniklaw fo elihw a retfA
nekcihc nomel fo dellems taht sreniatnoc hcnul dna skoob gnimag htiw moor eht otni delbmuts ydissaC ”!oyeH“
a ksa t’ndluoc uoY .kcals og sredluohs sih tlef gniwyerG
,ecaf sih ot nruter taeh eht tlef
.elbmuts mih gnikam ylraen
”?yako ,txen eb ot tnaw uoy ohw wonk em teL
,ereht deromra ssel dekool edih stI
”.ereh gnireffus eno eht m’I
emyhr ot derad taht eno—
,teehsdeb a tuo gniwollib enoemos ekil
.detcejretni belaC ”,no dloH“ —hcihw
.mih ksa ll’I ,worromoT
,meht ni eveileb lertsnim siht evah ot tol a tnaem tI
",ruodnelpS s'elgaE"
evah ot deraeppa tI
,elbat eht ta tas dna—
.dniw t’nsaw taht
.ebyam ,semag emoS“
.esahcrup rof sekips ynam sti gnisu
etul sih ta dekrow drofliM riS
.yawa gnirps ot emit dah ylerab eH
,ydissaC dias ”,oslA“
,mih drawot liat dekips ,evissam sti gnipeews dnA
.neercs emag reh revo pu dellac repinuJ
.romra sih ssorca dellips doolb der ,toh s’gniht eht dna
”.wob-wob-akcihc-wob taht no ni teg ot detnaw eH“
.gninrut ylno saw ti
”—evol gniydnu ruoy sseforp ,ti tog I ,haeY“
.seot eht yb detaerc stur eht otni smra sih hcterts dna
.dimuh ylegnarts dna ,elats
.sregnif reh neewteb dekeep repinuJ
,niarbdriB ,ereht yeH“
.thgil enivid gnitaidar erew srehtaef sih lla hguoht sa
.elttab ni decneirepxE
.dedrow-llew yltcaxe ton fi
.yrolg htiw gninihs
”,kcehc noitpecreP a em evig ,sedud ym ,yeH“  ”.ti llik s’teL“
.sredips fo mraws eht ta yltcerid ksalf eht gnilruh erofeb dias ehs
.gnihtyna yas dluoc I ,mih saw I nehW
,mih ta pu decnalg belaC
.elpoep ot gniklat ta doog uoy edam tahw saw tI .11 amsirahC
.deggurhs repinuJ ”.dnim reveN“ ”.ruoF“ ”.nevelE“ ”.xiS“
”.syug ,gnizama did uoY“
.koobemag sih morf pu dekool ydissaC
I fi nevE
?yeht t’ndluohs yhw dnA
.yawa seert llams gnippans
hteet toh ,prahs fo swor owt erofeb tuo drow eht tog ylerab eh tub
.tnemom looc a neeb adluoc tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tsif a dehcnelc neruaL ”.epoD .yako ,hO“
”.gnineppah ffuts dab ,hu eht
.seye sih dellor gniwyerG
”!sriatspu eerht rof moor tog eW
.tam emag eht no etul a gniyalp nogard ladepib a fo enirugif elttil a decalp ehS
;gnimoc ti nees evah dluohs eH
!eno wen a pu llor ot teg uoy won ,yeh tuB
.teehs retcarahc sih tA
.ton ro ti htiw saw eh rehtehw
”?od ot detnaw uoy gniht ehT
.ekarDnePehT ta
.pu-sbmuht delacs a htob meht evag dna demaeb eh gnos eht fo dne eht tA ”!tser
.erats yretaw a gniwyerG evag drofliM riS
.hcaer fo tuo tub
,splug ylnam wef a ni ela sih fo tser eht deffauq
.taorht reh deraelc repinuJ
.od nac ew gnihtemos eb ot sah
,retsnom eht nees dah eno oN
.snottub thgir eht lla dehsup itaoc eht tuoba gnihtemoS
edih ylacs ,delbbep a dah tI
,deromranu saw taorht stI
”.seert ro sllaw pu gnibmilc ,yzarc mom ruoy gnivird ,esuoh eht dnuora tsaf laer gninnur dna ,gniht gniklats eht enod ,nettik a erew uoy nehw ,wonk uoy
.detuohs gniwyerG ”!suolaej ton m’I“
,kcab sti pu delbmarcs dna
.derekcins rebbatspmuhC ”,suolaej s’eH
.gninrom txen eht litnu ecnahc rehtona teg t’ndluow eh ,won siht od t’ndid eh fi tub
.detagnole dna ladepib erew skcart eht tub ,nogard dias emoS
,teehs retcarahc sih pu dellup eh ,yllatneM ?ti diD
smra sti fo eno htiw epiws yldaed a tsrif gnigdod
,seirots lacol eht fo yna ni sredips eseht fo draeh d’eh fi llacer ot deirt nohpyrg ehT .gnitavilas
,dum ot htap eht denrut dah sniar ehT
:skcart sti dnuof d’yeht tub
.semit wef a liat reh dekcilf repinuJ
?evol tub ,hcnul rof uoy knird dna ,snagro ruoy yfiuqil ,daerht-ttub ni pu uoy parw ylno dluoc sredipS
.suoregnad ylbirret dna
?rettam ti did tahw tub
.dlrow eht sa ediw sa elims a mih gnivig
.evom ecnad hctap egabbac eht detnevni yltnerappa ehs neht dnA
.uoy lortnoc ti tel t’ndid uoy tub
”.ereh thgir stekcit sdriberiF tog I
,llebpmaC nayR yb
”.yaw a eb thgim erehT
”,evas edutitrof a emmig ,yknurd ,yeH“ .tahw rettam oN
.edis sih ta ylsselesu deppolf mra sih tub ,drows sih barg ot deirt eH
”?erots rouqil a bor ,od uoy d’tahW .aohW“
.elbat eht morf pu doots dna
,ymene gnirettihc eht dna dnuorg eht dekaos diuqil looC
.egneva ot dneirf a dna llik ot retsnom a evah syug esehT“
.mih no deppets tI
”?sredips emos pmots ot ydaer uoY“
.tuo semoc ti dna ,dnim ruoy no s’revetahw yas tsuj uoY
.laer s’ti erofeb efil ni od ot evah annog er’uoy ffuts eht lla yrt ot yaw A
.hself ditef dna taem gniyaced fo hcnets eht deirrac tI
.deneppah dah dab yllaer gnihtoN
”.ysae saw tahT .huH“
.mih ta lenrek nrocpop a dessot neruaL
murts-dim deye-ssorc tnew drofliM riS
,ti degdelwonkca uoY
.retcarahc a esol ot skcus syawlA“
.saw s’gniwyerG tuB
.ereh ton tub ,ma I ,llew—
neruaL neewteb riahc eht ni nwod deknulp eH
eno ni nwod eil dluoc eh egral os hcae
.tiftuo regnar tserof reh ta nwod dekool repinuJ
,drows trohs reh htiw
pmuhw duol a saw erehT
.suoreneg gnieb saw eh fi ,41 ta modsiW
.aH“ .daeha depmuts gniwyerG
.ti pleh t’ndluoc eh tub
!cih—tnaw uoY ?pu s’tahw
”.euqsallam a eb thgim ti kniht I ,skcart eht morf tub
wolleb ypsar ,gnidnirg ,elbirret a
.61 ta ,tseb sih saw ecnegilletnI
,tser ot emac yllanif dna
.ffo nrow yllanif gnivah monev eht fo stceffe gnibmun eht
.neruaL htiw edisni kcab tnew ydissaC
.71 fo amsirahc a dah dah gniwyerG
”?thgir ,rof er’yeht tahw s’tahT
,deddiks ,dellor tI
,resolc decnad eH
goD fo ecioV eht ot
.llew mih yalp ot elba neeb t’ndah
,dnuora ecam sih gniws ot rewop latnem hcum dedeen t’ndah gniwyerG
,esiarp fo lluf dna sdeed rieht tuoba eb dluow
.lufniap dekool tI
.gnihtemos htrow eb ot dah gniyalP
eenk eht fo kcab eht ssorca ti decils dah rebbatspmuhC tub ,stops kaew on
.em edisni s’taht gnihtyreve rof hguone gib t’nsi eciov yM
.ecaf sih no deretsalp nirg eguh a
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.egamad ecnegilletni od yeht ,sredips esehT .nam hO“
.teef sih ot flesmih dehsup gniwyerG
.gnihgual revo llef rebbatspmuhC ”!aH“ ”?diputs a m’I“
.mih morf dniw eht dekconk taht
.yaw siht emoc dah evissam gnihtemoS
.ti no gnikrow neeb d’eh tuB .11 amsirahC
.fo eerf llup etiuq t’ndluoc ti taht tniop a no kcuts dnim sih ,kcab devaw belaC
.tseb sih reven erew stats lacisyhp ehT
.efas s’taht yaw a ni ecitcarp s’tI .haeY“
,hsurbrednu eht gnihsurc ti fo thgiew suorednop eht
.smra sti htaeneb dna shgiht sti edisni sa llew sa
”.semutsoc ysatnaf no lla ti dneps ton dna ,repinuJ ,yenom evas yllautca nac elpoep emos wonk uoY“
”ruodnelpS s’elgaE“   :yojne esaelP
si yrots s’yadot dna
”?si gniht siht tahw aedi yna evah neve enoyna seoD“
”.renoos ti fo thguoht evah dluohs I
.uobirac eht ot dias belaC ”,enuJ ,iH“
,gninethgiarts kcab reh
,toob sih delkcat eno dna
,smoor tseug s’nrevat eht drawot sriats eht pu yldeticxe gnirepmacs ydaerla saw dlobok elttil ehT
.evaw lufreehc a mih evag dna mih was ydissaC
.mra eno rednu hsif dekooc-eciwt dna
.dluoc eh sa drah sa toob sih ta redips eht detnup
.snif rae sih ta gnihctulc
.taes sih ni elttil a nwod dehcnuh belaC
.tnanossid ylthgils ylno saw taht drohc a decudorp dna sgnirts eht ta dekculp snolat siH
.uoy ekil elpoep edam tahw saw tI
.dlrow eht sa ediw sa elims a ydissaC evag eH
”.dab a saw yeht dna sadiops dellik eW .hhhhU“
.sgnirts etul sih revo nrettap lacigam a decnad snolat s’drofliM riS
.retcarahc a esol ot dekil eno on tub
”—fo eceip suortsnom ,diputs uoy ,uoy tog eW“
?em htiw emag sdriberiF a ot og uoy lliW
,dezafnu demees snoinapmoc stI
gniliec eht drawot gnirats eno rebmun a
.walc sti morf epiws a deppetsedis ,liat sti fo peews rehtona revo ylbmin deppoh eH
,eulc a dah enoyna fI
,dliw eht ni devil lla ew fi
.seenk sti dehcaer ylno meht fo hcae taht eguh os
.rehtegot gnikrow eb ot desoppus er’eW
.mih ot txen pu deklaw repinuJ ”.nam ,yeH“
,esool dna tfos hself eht
.krow ot gniog saw ti woh dnatsrednu t’ndid yllaer
.ti ekil tlef eh ,eciwt ro ecno tuB .t’ndid belaC os
”—ot detnaw eh fi ksa did I ,yawynA“
”.pu peek ,mudmud ,no emoc ,haeY“
.erofeb sksalf esoht nees d’eH
,dedne dah gnos eht litnu detiaw eH
.ni tuc repinuJ ”,yakO“
.sciryl s’drofliM riS deinapmocca yllausu taht
suoregnad ylhgih ,hu tuB“
.daeh ym ,sdog hO .sdog hO“
.mih ta hgual dluoc ydissaC dnA
thguoht fo niart s’gniwyerG ”.naem em sekaM
,toh saw seert eht rednu dniw ehT
.srae sih revo sdnah htob tup drofliM riS ”.duol os ton ,hgU“
suoixna saw eh nehw tibah dab a—
:noisses tsal s’emag eht fo dne eht ta
.gnihtyna rof ecitcarp t’nsaw gniyalpelor tuB
”.ti teg etiuq t’ndid I ?erew sretcarahc ruoy esuaceb etad ot evah dluow uoy fo owt eht neht dna drofliM etad ot gniog gniwyerG saW
.rehtael denehguot eht ecreip t’ndluoc sgnaf sti tub ,drah gnitib
moor eht otni yaw reh dewoble neruaL ”?sdren ,puddaW“
.wow …tub ,nam ,saw ereht hsiw I“ ”.noitop A
,emag a ni deyalp uoy retcarahc bmud a revo yrc ot diputs saw tI
.kcab gniog sredluohs dna
.tuo ksa ot ysae eb dluohs ohw nosrep fo dnik ehT
.meht ot kcab teg retteb I
”.emit taerg a eb annog’s—eb annog’S“
,yruf dna niap ni niaga deraor tI
.tnenoppo sih gnissessa
.fo tros ,gniht ruasonid s’tI“
.draykcab s’repinuJ ni ynomerec lairub a neht dna
,degaruocne tlef ehs taht llet dluoc gniwyerG
.lacitirc eht tuohtiw neve orez ot mih nekat evah dluow taht wolb a no egamad elbuod ,tih lacitirC
ereh morf hcaer dluoc eh ecalp gnikool-rednet ylno eht ssorca dehsals eh
,dna thgin yreve kcotsevil gniruoved neeb dah taht retsnom emos fo liart eht no tnes neeb d’yehT
eye dettils eht ekil
.flesmih dlot eh ,worromoT
ecam sih gnuws eH
.ti no trid emos htiw dnuorg eht ni repap fo eceip a saw ereht esuaceb tsuj yawa og t’ndid
”.edud ym ,selor eht ekam attog uoY
seires sreraeB eriF gninniw-drawa eht fo rohtua
?sihT“ .drofliM riS ta detuohs eh
tuo esle enoemos ksa ot semit doog fo tsil eht ,sulP
.segde tfos htiw tub ,gnortS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.gniog saw siht erehw sseug dluoc belaC
.suoregnad saw tahT
.gnignis erew sdrib oN
”—nac—nac eh neht dna ,ruodnelpS s’elgaE tsac nac eh nehw tnemom a em evig ll’uoy tub ,haeY“
”.bmud sdnuoS“ .wonk ot detnaw rebbatspmuhC
.drows eht eerf yrp ot gniyrt ,snolat-elkcis devruc htiw ecaf sti ta ylsselesu gniwalc
.elttab cipe rieht fo sgnos htiw nrevat eht edaneres drofliM riS gnihctaw dna ela sih gnippis ,elbat nrevat a ta tas gniwyerG
”?sriats eht dnif mih pleh dna rovaf a gard a od uoy dluoW
”.os sseug I“ .dias eh ”,haeY“
,edis rieht ta drofliM riS htiW
,kcik ecreif a htiw ,dna kcab gel eno dekcoc eH .eof yna taefed
.gnizama er’uoy kniht I
sffur keehc sih ta debbur belaC
.txen gnimoc saw tahw wenk eh tnaem hcihW .liO
,etoyoc a rof gnitadimitni yllufwa saw neruaL
swap sih htiw ecaf sih derevoc belaC ”!oN“
.evitisop syawla enoemos—
swaperof sti fo snolat ekil-ehtycs eht taht wol os dehcuorc tub sgel owt no doots tI
,gniwyerG eb ot woH .denrael d’eH
.detsaw saw eh nehw tuo yug
,thgir erew sregalliv eht fi
.romra sih htaeneb rehtegot kcab flesti gnittink hself dna elcsum fo gnileef eht ta thgit kaeb sih gnipmalc
.rof er’yeht tahw tuoba erom gnikniht saw I“
legna na ekil eciov a htiw nogard gninnirg ,ygdup a ot on yas dluoc eno on yltnerappA
.gniwyerG dekil dah enoyrevE
”.erus roF“ .delggig neht
?thginot siht rof ydaer uoy …uoY
.daed repus si gniwyerG
.nepeed dna nekrad ot demees tserof eht ni swodahs ehT
,hu ,eht tahw rettam on
”?thgir ,gniticxe s’tahT
enigami ot deirt eh sa skcart sti depmuj ylfeirb
,erutaerc suortsnom eht dniheb tsuJ
,noitop a deplug ylkciuq dna
?thgir ,yalp tsuj reven s’ti ,gniyalp dnuora nur uoy dna dik a er’uoy nehw ,ekiL
.tuo eye na tup d’I
”.gnikrap s’eH .em thguorb eH“