lerriuqs eht ot nevig saw trihs pmad ylthgils ehT
.sretsam tneicna eht yb detfarc saw taht ydob reppu na gnirab
.revo dedaeh eh os
htgnel sih morf wap s’tar eht devom eH
,revol sih ekorts ot htrof dna kcab wap sih thguorb eh sa
.eloh knip s’tar eht htiw kcoc sih pu denil eh sa pu liat sih deknay dna spih s’yob eht fo dloh koot nosaM
roolf elit eht no nwod tas eH
,ereeeeeH“ .draugydob sih ot flesmih tneserp ot
esnopser ni dennirg regnis ehT
,shtaerb rieht dleh enoyreve sa tlah a ot emoc dah emit fo cirbaf yrev ehT
.regit emosdnah eht decudes gnivah reve detterger d’eh taht yad a neeb t’ndah erehT
,ereht ni klaw tsuj ot dewolla saw eh ylno
.thgin yb retirw dna recnad a dna
”,won yb taht wonk dluohs elpoep lla fo uoY .trecnoc a retfa ma syawla I“
.reh ta gnilims elihw deksa eh
.taerg saw trecnoc eht tub ,detsuahxe m’I“
elbat llams a ot revo deklaw eh sa
.sba leets s’revol sih morf yawa flesmih dehsup ylmrif tar eht
,eugnot hguor sih htiw elzzum s’leinahT dezies eh dna
.od ot boj a dah eh taht flesmih gnidnimer erofeb
,emarf daorb s’nosaM dnuora smra sih devom eH
.emod siht ni tif elpoep ynam woh tsuj enasni saw tI
,nosaM rof hcum oot devorp noos gnikorts eltneg ehT
,tar sih naht lufituaeb erom erutaerc elgnis a ton saw ereht ,nosaM oT
.tar eht dnuora smra sih depparw dna
secnefed sih tsap eugnot sih gnirehtils yb mih dedrawer ohw
.ti gnikcil ylwols erofeb
.tuo detniop eh ”,trecnoc a retfa uoy ot klat ot semoc syawla eH
si yrots s’yadot dna
,stiftuo tnereffid neves naht ssel on hguorht tnew dna
rae sih ni delworg eh
yawa reh gnidael
,tniop taht ta shtnom ruof tuoba rof draugydob lanosrep s’leinahT neeb dah regit llat ehT
,esualppa gninefaed-rae na retfA
”,leinahT ,llew os sredro wollof uoY !yob dooG“ ”!haA“
.nageb gnilggah eht dna
.teg dluohs eh lrig fo epyt tahw wenk eh os
noissimrep sih deddon regit eht litnu t’nsaw tI
.niaga revo dna revo tops lufrednow taht gnittih
-oy did erehW ?nosaM“
.rotcetorp sih ta pu dekool dna
si dworc ylevil a rof gnimrofreP
,rennam detnioppasid a ni detcaer mih fo tnorf ni thgir elpoep ehT
.mih detneserper taht lamina deffuts edamdnah a thguac neve dratsab htooms eht dna
.sgnaf reh gnikcil erofeb dias terref etihw a
,srae sih ni sgnicreip elpitlum eht yb detcelfer thgil
seye sih desolc nosaM
sgnos evol suomaf tsom sih fo eno lrig eht gnas leinahT
sih ot ecaf s’regit eht denrut eH
nwohs saw oediv A
.gel s’nosaM dnuora flesti gnipparw ylwols liat sih ,dias eh
.gnineve taht edul yllanoitpecxe gnieb saw draugydob eht thguoht eH
taem evitisnes eht detcetorp yllamron taht htaehs yzzuf eht no elkcus dluoc eh os
,ecafrus tew eht nwod edils ylwols knups sih dehctaw dna
.rorrim eht ni flesmih ta kcab gnikool dna
,tcnitsni dna tsul yb gnivirD
dias regit egral eht ”,em
.elzzum detagnole s’regnis eht fo esu doog gnikam dna
.tey ton ,yttik ,tey toN“
mhtyhr sih tsol eH
.ezirp sih mialc ot nwod tnew eh sa
gnileef siht yojne retteb ot
.gnilims elihw dias eh
pil rewol sih tib dna
,hctorc sih tsniaga tar eht dellup ylgnorts eH
.wohs eht retfa ti tuoba sdneirf sih dna tar eht llet yletinifed d’eH
hcae demaor swap rieht elihw delgnatne seugnot rieht ,ssik etamitni peed a derahs owt ehT
,hcamots dna tsehc s’regit eht nwod wap sselruf a devom eH
,daeh sih otni gnippop nup diputs taht rof flesmih ta dennirg ev’dluow nosaM
,gnol erofeb ecap ecin a tes eh os
yltfos yrev denaom tar ehT
.dias ynnub a ”!ereht pu em teg uoy fi skcub ytfif uoy evig ll’I !ris ,no emoC“
.yob eht esaet ot taem sih gnilcric
.ereht dna ereh sekatsim wef a edam d’eh os
.siht ekil lodi rieht ees dluoc snaf sih ylno fI
yaw eht fo tuo liat sih gnitfil dna kcab sih gnihcra
.thgir saw emit eht nehw ,yad eno laiciffo ti ekam neve d’eh spahreP
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,kcen sih tib regit eht nehw egde eht revo devohs ylhguor saw tar eht rof
.elpoep ,ereh kcab eb ot gnizama s’ti ,doG
.uoy htiw gnileef siht erahs dluoc I hsiw I
.emoc noos dluow tnemom siH
,os ro hcni rehtona ni kcoc s’nam eht decrof eH
”?leinahT rof siht sI“
,yltneg ti dezeeuqs dna kcid enilef kciht eht dnuora depparw sregnif s’regnis ehT
.mih ot ti nworht d’ohw lrig eht ta dekniw dna
.dnuora llits saw regit eht suht
.elims a htiw dias tar ydnas eht
.moorhtab tnecajda eht otni dna
.pmur ylevol s’elam eht tsniaga hctorc sih mals ot ylno
.seenk sih otno flesmih gnirewol dna
.desaet draugydob eht
,pmur ylepahs eht otno nwod dils ylwols
.secnefed s’yob eht fo tsal eht nwod gnikaerb
,lausu sa tniop-no saw gnicnad siH
.pu kcab gnidnats dna
.pu mih gnilir rof owt ro kcirt a pu dekcip d’eh
,hcum oot tib elttil a tsuj ti detnaw ohw seno eht gnidiovA
.swap reh htiw detegdif ehs sa
,bmuht sih gnizeeuqs yb
”sepirtS sih gninraE“
.pu kcab gnitteg elihw
,niaga etatsorp sih tsniaga pu gnitsurht detrats regit eht sa ylduol denaom
.ralupop saw rats gnuoy gnisir eht taht esirprus on saw tI
trihs dna tekcaj sih denottubnu eh sa
mih ta delworg dah flow ehT
”?em rof ton s’taht erus uoy erA“
.detcaer yksuh a ”!taht elbuod ll’I“
.ydob toh sih fo edisni flesmih detlih dna deraor regit eht nehw
,htgnel gnikael eht dnuora
ni kcab mals ot ylno
.waj s’elam regral eht no delbbin yllufyalp dna
,hguoht eb ot tnaem t’nsaw tI
,sdnoces evif tuoba tsuj rof snoitome rieht ni dednepsus ecneidua eht gnivael
.tac eht morf snaorg derusaelp erom gniward
.sserP terreF deR dna
.niaga noitnetta ta dnats ot gninrut erofeb
.llaw kcils eht tsniaga pu dees tar fo epor retfa epor gnitoohs
,yaw eht lla elzzum sih denepo eh litnu tar eht gnisaet no tpek eH
,tib a kcab gninael elihw yldetaeper siht did eH
,ecap wols sih htiw yob eht gnirutrot no tpek eH
.hguoht tnemom etiruovaf s’nosaM t’nsaw sihT
ti ta dekool dna deremmats nam ehT
.niaga esion gnippals lufituaeb taht gnitaerc
.esruoc fo ,gninialpmoc saw eh taht toN
”.yggit ,tsrif enim uoy ekam I fi toN“
.spih s’tar eht otni gniggid swalc krad sih
ylduol denaom eH
,elttil a tuo gnillup ylwols elihw
.ecaf sih delkcit sreksihw s’tac eht sa delggig dna
llaw rewohs eht tsniaga flesmih decarb tar ehT
ruf deruoloc-dnas eht ni sliart gnivael swalc sih
.repmihw dna elbmert ot mih gnisuac dna
.niard eht nwod gniog retaw eht yb yawa tpews saw ti erofeb
.taht ekil egrahc koot nosaM nehw ti devol eH
.nurrevo yliraropmet erew sessecorp thguoht sih taht ton ti erew
.era uoy ereht ,nosaM ,hA“
dias syawla dah leinahT ,revewoH
gnignis elihw tsehc sih ot ti dleh tar ehT
.egats eht otno pu lrig a detivni tar eht
swap siH .niaga revo lla htuom railimaf eht gnirolpxe
delkcuhc dna daeh sih koohs nosaM
.siht fo leinahT dednimer netfo eh dna
ecnef eht revo lrig lerriuqs eht depleh eH
.tsehc sih morf swap sih devomer dna
.taht ekil mih gnisaet sbrab yhself eht htiw nepo htuom sih gnipeek elbuort fo tol a gnivah saw leinahT
,selamef regae ynam eht fo eno tceles ot nosaM ot pu saw tI
.gnilims elihw yltfos ekops regit eht
,gnol tiaw ot evah t’ndid eh ,ylikcuL
.hguoht erus rof wenk eh erofeb
selit etihw eht tsniaga daeherof sih detser rats ehT
.ecnef eht morf kcab deppets ehs erofeb
.seenk sih otno nwod knas ylwols eh sa
,llaw eht tsniaga revo tneb dna dnuora denrut eh sa
.gniod saw eh tahw fo weiv doog a dah eh os
,oediv eht morf tar emas yrev eht no nwod enohs thgiltops eht erofeb
,tsehc daorb s’regit sih tsniaga kcab gninael tar eht
”,em htiw yalp dna rood eht kcol ,no emoC
.ecaf s’ytirbelec eht revo lla pit sih debbur ylwols eh sa gnikrims elihw
.renwo sti morf lworg yppah a gniward
”,ti ot no dloh…he ll’I .uoy knaht…mhU“
.niaga noitom ni tes eb dluow dlrow eht taht tnemom eht rof gnitiaw
,steppins eht htiw gnola gnas dworc ehT
.tar eht morf naom rehtona gniward ,ylmrif ti dedaenk dna
.gnieb eritne sih hguorht gnisruoc
tar deruoloc-dnas emosdnah a fo
.xaler yllanif dluoc regit eht
.tog eh traeh der eht pu gnidloh erofeb dias eh
.dlofnet yb deilpitlum seirc s’elpoep eht
,seye eniramauqa sih htiw aremac eht otni thgir gnirats tar eht htiw dedne yllautneve oediv ehT
.tnemom taht ta elzzum sih ni ylgguns os detser taht
s’leinahT ot no swap sih devom dna regnis eht ot pu tnew eh sa
dnuora denrut yllautneve tar ydnas ehT
.slrig deganeet dna nemow gnuoy fo detsisnoc ecneidua eritne eht fo tnecrep ytenin tuoba ecnis ,egnellahc eht etiuq saw hcihw
,sehtolc sih ffo deggurhs dna ti dekcol ylluferac eH
.sruoloc eht egnahc dluoc yeht taht os
.stsitra pu-ekam dna ,ffats V/A
.ssenkraD   naloaF yb
mlap sih ni dnuora meht gnillor
sba s’nam eht neewteb enil eht gniwollof
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tfel dah esle ydobyreve retfa niaga tuo emoc dluow uoy taht gnipoh tpek ohw snaf emos erew ereht ,haeY“
.gninraw ni reh ta regnif a gnitniop dna kcab lrig a gnihsup retfa
.mih rof meht trap d’eh gnipoh
”,uoy htiw esuom dna tac emos yalp ot doom eht ni m’I
”,regit emosdnah uoy ,wohs eht retfa emit doog a uoy evig ll’I“
,gnilims elihw srae s’leinahT no sessik elttil teews detnalp nosaM
.mih dnuora derettacs srorrim
guh a tog ehs retfa
,efas dna elbatrofmoc leef mih edam nosaM taht
niaga seye dlareme sih denepo regit ehT
”.em teg dna emoc emoS“
.dnuos fo llaw gninefaed-rae eno otni gnidnelb
,ti htiw shtped sti derolpxe dna eveels derruf eht otni eugnot sih deppils eH
ydob sih nwod dewolf retaw eht elihw kcoc drah sih gnikorts tar eht fo thgis ehT
.nosaM ni tseretni laiceps a dah ratspop eht taht saw
.daeh sih koohs dna
.raer tcefrep s’tar eht otni raeppasid kcoc taf sih gnihctaw naht erom no mih denrut gnihtoN
.rehtie gniyrt fo kcal rof ton dna
.wap sih ni retaw larenim fo elttob a dna
,kcab s’regnis eht dekorts yltneg wap eerf siH
.citarre erom emaceb stsurht s’regit eht
.srae sih fo tuo sgnirrae revlis eht koot dna
lausu sa ylsselwalf gniht sih did tsuj leinahT
.ylthgirb hsulb dna pu tuhs ot mih desuac kcoc s’regit eht yb pals eltneg a erofeb detrats tar eht “-I ,lleW“
,hguoht ydaerla semit nezod a siht enod dah eH
,tsrif rewohs a ekaT“
.ti fo dne eht ta trihs sih ffo gnikat pu dedne dna
.deretlaf reven eciov sih dna
,tar eht dnuora roolf eht no dednal straeh dna srewolF
.ecalp ni mih gnidloh dna
.gnidliub eht fo tuo elpoep gnioohs erew uoy elihw fo erac nekat neeb ydaerla s’tahT“
.esruoc fo enola erew yeht nehw ylnO
,yad eht gnirud rehcaet hsilgnE na si ohw ,naloaF yb
.tniop taht ta edam syawla nam eht sesion elbaroda eht morf gnimmuc saw regit eht llet dluoc eH
,elihw a rof taht ekil detser yehT
,eugnot htooms eht revo pit debrab sih debbur yltneg eh sa dias eh
”,uoy rof s’ti ,oN“
erofeb naht repeed elttil a pih s’tar eht otni gud swalc siH
.ni kcab ti hsup ot ylno
”?yob ,siht tnaw uoy od hcum woH“
.tar ytrid uoy ,taht ekil ytaews er’uoy nehw em hcuot t’nod
.seenk sih otno nwod elam rellams eht dehsup eh yltnetsisni woh ni tnedive saw hcihw
.niaga kcoc kcils sih pu gninil erofeb erom ecno eloh eht ta taps eH
yltfos derepmihw eH
.evila nosrep tsegnorts eht ekil leef mih edam tI
,sgel sih no delbmert dna
,spil s’elam rellams eht ta kcil ot eugnot sih tuo gnitrad ,kcab dessik dna
mlap sih ni gnitser taem toh eht fo gnileef yvaeh eht devol tar ehT
,hteet prahs sih htiw kcen s’egrahc sih dehtuom draugydob eht
.lla ti ot noitasnes artxe na gnidda rewohs eht morf retaw eht
desaet eh ”,yttik ,yttik
.nwo sih htiw ti decalper dna
delworg enilef ehT
.pu daeh sih detlit eh sa
,dnoces eht yb resolc gnitteg xamilc sih fo gnileef eht tA
ffurcs s’yob eht gnitib
.gnineppah egnarts gnihtyna tuohtiw ylhtooms ytterp tnew trecnoc eht fo tser ehT
,hguoht terces-pot eb ot saw sihT
,deraeppasid ylneddus gnileef eht nehw
,tnempiuqe s’maet thgil eht ot deknil wohemos erew yehT
.ecalp drah a dna kcor a neewteb tar eht gnippart yllaretil
.straeh fo tseici eht neve tlem dluow taht kool a nam eht gnivig dna
.yaw rieht teg ot gniyrt elpoep fo stpmetta elituf hcus yb dezafnu saw draugydob ehT
.regit sih morf snaom duol gniward
.revol sih htiw rehtegot esaeler sih evah dluoc eh litnu kcab dloh ot detnaw eH
.lrans a htiw liat dekan eht pu deknay eh dna
!neetxis naht redlo hcum neeb evah ylbissop t’ndluoc lrig ehT
,swap gnorts s’nam eht otni kcab ttub elbbub sih gnisserp dna
.nam eht ecudes rehtruf ot tpmetta na ni spih sih deyaws eh sa
wohS .eituc ,sdrow htiw toN“
,naloaF yb ”sepirtS sih gninraE“ saw sihT
dias eh ”,esle erehwemos dees ruoy tnaw I
”?tey ,emit doog a gnivah uoy erA !enoyreve ,olleH“ .dworc eht ta devaw tar ydnas eht
.esac ni tsuj yb gnidnats cidem a ees dluoc regit eht dna
slrig suoivne sseltnuoc fo smaercs dna seirc ehT
,elam rellams eht otni kcab htgnel lluf sih devohs nosaM
regit eht ot doog os detsat eH
,htgnel elohw sih gnisu
,stsilyts ,sdraug ytiruces rehto ot desoppo sa
,retaw revo gniklaw
.ecaf s’regnis eht ssorca daerps nirg suoveihcsim a
,sih ni wap s’lerriuqs eht koot dna edis eht ot devom ydaerla dah tar eht
.tlep depirts s’revol sih tops yletaidemmi t’ndid eh nehw denworf dna redluohs sih revo dekool leinahT
taorht sih fo kcab eht ni yltnasaelp delbmur delworg A
,hguoht reverof pu ti peek t’ndluoc eh wenk eH
.nosaM ta gnilims dna gnikniw retfa
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
kcab sih gnihcrA
,egrahc sih otni gnihsup erofeb desaet eh ,”’haa‘ yaS“
.yttik ,pu kcuts os eb t’nod ,rrmmH“ ”.klat ll’ew neht
.ecivres-naf saw ti neht
.ruf trohs sih hguorht gnivom swalc prahs eht fo
.tius sih denethgiarts dna
.reerac sih deregnadne evah thgim ti rof
tar eht ot derednerrus draugydob ehT
.kcab reh gnitrocse erofeb flesmih ot derettum eh
,htuom sih gnikcuf detrats regit eht sa ecalp ni daeh sih gnidloh
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
!eno txen eht rof ydaer teg ,wohynA
?reganam eht tuoba tahW“
.delkcuhc dna ti ta dekool leinahT ”!tog I tahw kooL“
,ot pu saw nam eht tahw ees ot redluohs sih revo dekool eh nehw tsuJ
.mih ot emoc ot lerriuqs a denoitom eh
,eno yb eno gnir sih ta gnikculp sbrab yhself sih leef ot elba eb dluow tar eht erus gnikam
,elzzum sih ni borht dna elbmert enilef eht tlef eh ecnO
sredluohs sih revo lewot pmad a
nehw ro egats no elihw eb yam tar eht ohcam revewoH
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
,der denrut ecalp eht ni sthgil lla dna
.egats eht otno stfig gniworht trats ot elpoep rof euc eht saw siht ,yltnerappA
.pal s’draugydob eht ni kcab gnittis erofeb
stsirw eht yb leinahT koot yltneg eh sa dias nam eht
dias eh ”,-uoy– kcuF .eituc ,on hO“
.ti no traeh eht decalp dna
.swap htob ni ti dleh eh sa
.niaga gnivom detrats dah regit eht sa erom emos gninaorg dna gninaom erofeb hteet dehcnelc hguorht dessih ytirbelec eht ”…uoy kcuf…F“
gnilggig erofeb dias ehs
egats eht otno reh detrocse dna
.os gniod retfa yletaidemmi tsomla ti ta gnikcus
.seidob s’rehto
,noitcaer evitisop a gnitteg retfA
,revol gib sih yb llaw eht tsniaga pu dehsup saw leinahT
,tniaf ot tuoba saw ehs ekil dekool lerriuqs ehT
.hsulb ot yob eht gnisuac
.ecnis detnioppasid neeb reven d’eH
snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb seigolohtna ni dehsilbup seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,moor eht tfel dah snaf eht fo tsal eht retfa hgis gnol a tuo gnitteL
.ydob delcsum sih hguorht gnitarbiv sevawdnuos eht fo
,moor neerg sih ni tar eht dnif d’eh wenk nosaM
”sepirtS sih gninraE“:yojne esaelP
yawa ecaf sih llup ot lortnoc-fles sih fo lla koot ti taht
.yltnacifingis pu deps eh sa gnitnurg dna
htaerb sih fo mih gnibbor
,dias eh ”,egassam gnixaler a fo deen ni m’I kniht I“
”?gnileef uoy era woH“
”,evila netae teg ot gniog si lrig roop tahT“
,tih tsetal sih fo eton tsrif eht otni dehcnual eh sA .hself eht ni
.elzzum gnippird s’yob eht fo pot no taem yvaeh sih debbob dna
nirg duorp a htiw derewsna regit eht ”,flesreh em dlot ehS .erus yreV“
kcehc ni xelfer gag sih peek ot deganam tar ehT
,stnemrag gniniamer sih fo dir gnitteg dna tleb sih gniodnu retfA
.pmur s’elam rellams eht ta ylirgnuh gnippal dna
.draugydob sih ot revo yaw sih edam dna riahc sih morf pu doots ylwols eh sa dias regnis eht
,tsrif ta dimit neeb dah nam ehT
”,yadot ydeen er’uoY“ .spih
,rorrim a fo tnorf ni sseltrihs tar eht dnif ot rood eht denepo eH
,ylluftsul yawa gniwolp
,draugydob lanosrep eht sA
,hgrU“ .tsehc daorb s’nosaM no swap sih decalp eh sa eciov yklis a no gnittup
,ecaf s’tac eht otni kcab pmur sih dehsup dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,shtnom wef eseht nI
.roolf elit a no nwod gniniar retaw fo dnuos eht ta pu dekrep srae siH
.meht fo owt eht no nwod deniar retaw rewohs eht os tib a kcab detoocs dna
gnilims elihw dehsulb dna
,sllab yzzuf s’elam tnanimod eht rof tuo dehcaer dna
,snaf sih gniteem
yawa gniward erofeb
spil sih dekcil dna delkcuhc eH
seye sih desolc yob ehT
”,gnitsugsid s’tahT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.gnos gnidnopserroc eht yb deinapmocca oediv cisum a fo trap a wohs dluow ti
gnilworg detrats dna
.htiw pu mih gnillif saw regit eht hcni elgnis yreve leef dluow tar eht erus ekam ot
,thgis looc yllaer a saw tI
.kcab depirts eht gnikorts
elttob eht nwod tup eH
,srae s’nam eht dehcaer
.rood eht ot gniklaw elihw
,gnos poh pih looc yllaer a saw tI
,eno otni kool ot esohc eh revenehW
.snaf eht fo eno yb gnihtyna detfig neeb eh dah erofeb reveN
rood a hguorht deklaw eh sa dias tar eht
.ecnartne s’enilef eht ta gninaom morf kcab peek ot elbanu saw dna depsag tar regnuoy ehT
erusaelp fo evaw retfa evaw fo tluassa tnatsnoc eht yb delbmarcs saw dnim siH
seciov fo sdnasuoht
,pmur sih no gnitcilfni saw regit eht tnemhsinup suoiciled eht gniyojne ylippah saw eH
,egats no erew yeht ecnO
yltfos yob eht dedlocs eh ”…tneitapmi oS“
,emit emas eht ta llaw elit eht otni mih gnihsup elihw
elttob sih morf gniknird erofeb deksa eh
.dlrow eht ni gnileef citsatnaf tsom eht saw sihT
daeh reh koohs lrig ehT
,egrahc sih ta nwod dennirg eH
”,hguone gnol uoy kooT
,kcoc sih ot pih s’tar eht morf wap sih devom dna spil sih dekcil eH
flesmih ot delkcuhc eH
.hguoht hcum taht gnicnad morf truh seenk dna kcab yM
nemodba sih ni gnidaerps htmraw railimaf eht tlef eh litnu t’nsaw tI
.gnos lanif a htiw wohs eht gnidne dna
,egats eht gnikcor leinahT ta ecnalg tsal eno elots eH
.mih morf detnaw eh tahw raelc etiuq ti edam dah tar eht litnu
”,rettar ,enim uoy ekam ylreporp lliw I ,yad enO“
gnileef eht devol eh taht raelc ti edam rats eht
mih tsniaga pu leinahT dellup nosaM
.efil ot emac neercs eguh a sa dworc eht morf pu esor smaercS
”,yawa meht dnes ot dah yllautca eW
.gnos dnoces eht htiw gniunitnoc erofeb
.kcoc sih dnuora gnimriuqs nam rehtona gnivah ekil etiuq gnihton saw erehT
.rats eht htiw eifles a nekat dah dna
”,tahwemos xaler nac I os ,syad wef a rof trecnoc rehtona evah t’now I gniht doog a s’tI
ecnart trohs sih morf kcab dellup saw eH
.hgis a htiw daeh sih ekahs ot mih gnisuac
detuohs eh ”!pu elkcuB
.gnilias htooms neeb syawla t’ndah ti dna
.rats liat thgit sih tsniaga pu flesti gnidlof eugnot hguor s’regit yklub eht fo gnileef eht yb trohs tuc saw noitseuq s’regnis ehT ”!haa
,wonk t’ndid ylbaborp reganam eht tahW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.ytpme mih gnivael
,selit yreppils ,tew eht no skram on tfel ylikcul swalc sih dna
,drah emac eh sa yltneloiv gnikcohs ydob sih
mih htiw mih koot eH
ylwols yrev ti gniod
.tnetnoc yllufrednow gnileef
,skeehc sih otno devom swap mraw s’nosaM sa ylippah denaom dna
.htaehs taf s’regit eht ni gnirrits a esuac yletaidemmi ot hguone saw
,swalc gnorts s’nosaM yb nepo ediw daerps erew skeehc ttub siH
,ylthgils gnihsulb ,dias eh
.yadot dliw tnew dworc ehT
spil tevlev sih desolc regnis eht taht
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.elttil a eugnot sih tuo gnikcits neve
.ekil ylurt saw eh tahw wenk nosaM
gnimoc rof enoyreve gniknaht erofeb
.dnaherofeb redro ro yub dluoc elpoep taht skcits thgil laiceps eht gnidulcni
.reve gniht tseb eht hcum ytterp
!enod raen erehwon era ew esuaceB !dooG“
,meht no gniggut yltneg dna
.redluohs ralucsum eht tsniaga kcab daeh sih gnitser
”,ybab ,ti s’taht ,heH“
,ta dellecxe tar eht gnihtyna saw ereht fI
.mih ot traeh a tuo dleh lrig regit a nehw desirprus saw draugydob ehT
.egats depahs-ssorc eht fo elddim eht sdrawot gniklaw elihw deksa eh
.moorhtab eht ot yaw sih edam enilef eht
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dne on ot mih derettalf dna desirprus tI
.elcsum deniart-llew sih gnigassam dna
,gnos htfif sih roF
.elttil a ti gnilkcit
.lla sih ti gnivig yletinifed saw leinahT dna
llaw eht tsniaga flesmih decarb tar ehT
,nirg a htiw niaga tuo dellup tac gib ehT
,boj eht ot wen ylevitaler saw eH
.spil s’enilef eht no ssik etanoissap a detnalp dna
tuo kcab ti gnillup erofeb tib a dnuora elcsum elisneherp sih delggiw dna taht ta dennirg regit ehT ”!kcuffff ,hO“
.kcab dehcra sih fo evruc eht gnola devom walc sih sa