.ti nees evah ot dah ehS
.daeh ruoy ni sesion evissesbo ,gnidnilb ,yrgna ,esnesnon
.smetsys ytiruces emoh gnillatsni ro
,hguoht ti teg I kniht I
.kcen ym no htaerb reh gnileef dna skceB htiw deb ni gniyal llits m’I ,enohp ym gnikcehc llits m’I
,siht hsurc ot evah I
.em ot gniyl s’ehS
.maerd a tsuj eb ot sdeen tI
,meht ta gnikool neve
?gniht tab a s’ti fi tahw ,onnud I …s’ti fi tahW ?taht retfA
.tihs nwo ym revo teg
.reh rof rettalp a no flesym tup gnikcuf tsuj yllaer
?enola uoy evael t’nac ti tub
,em fo trap gnitsugsid siht ecaf naht rehtar flesym tae yllaretil
,evael ot deen tsuj I
,seirots dlo eht rebmemer I tub
dna tsul dna rorroh fo selat gnitnuah eht rebmemer I
?doolb ruoy kcus ot dneirf
?tuc eht ekam ehs did peed woh …woH
?huh ,thguoht rehtona s’tahT .taht deliaf I
,oot reh evol I reh llet d’I
.evisneffo yllacisab  s’ti ,gnihtyna fI
,ereh llits m’I esuaceb
.gnihton rof tnaw dluohs I
…t’nac tsuj I elihw reh no gnignah
—  …demahsa ylraelc os s’ehS
dna klat ylerar eW
t’nac ehS  —  -esaelp dog ho kaerf a sa em fo kniht t’nseod ehs tahT
:ruf dna hself ot skcits doolb yaw ehT
.ton m’I gnihtyreve s’ehS
gnihtyna em dnes ot erac neve t’ndid
.enoemos no pu gnuh htob er’ew sseug I …roop
,reh esol ot tnaw t’nod I
siht gniyas dlo elttil a tsomla leef I
.doolb s’dneirf tseb ym knird ot tnaw I  .uoy gnizinoga
,taht …tsuj m’I tub
,yaw nwo reh ni em evol neve yam ehs taht wonk I
.edistuo syats ti regnol eht reikcits gnitteg ylno
?enola uoy evael t’nac ti tub ,dab si wonk
.cigam tsuj s’ti klat ew nehw tub
.taem eht fo enon
skceB htiw deb ni sthgin ylenol yllaer esoht nO
klof suoititsrepus
,yad yreve ,gnignol dna doolb tsuj s’tI
.gnorw gnihton s’erehT  —  -ria emos dedeen tsuj I etunim a ni kcab eb ll’I ,gnihtyna sdeen ehs fi
,tuoba yzarc m’I enoemos htiw gnivil m’I ,eerged ym no gnikrow m’I ,llew gniog eb ot desoppus era sgnihT
ecitcarp eW .sthgil eht no nrut eW .rood eht
,relevart wollef ruoy
traeh ym fo thgiliwt eht ni evil dna flesym tae rehtar d’I
ot tnaw em sekam tsomla ti
.siht gniod peek nac I regnol hcum woh wonk t’nod I tub
—  .em ot gniyl s’ehS
…tsuj I laeppa eht teg I
,yaw nwo reh ni em evol seod  ehs ebyam taht dna
.gnikool ton m’I skniht ehs nehw enohp reh gnikcehc syawla tsuj s’ehs ,meht ot sdnopser eh kniht neve t’nod I
.em htiw gnorw si kcuf eht tahW
,nosrep eltbus a ton m’I
.das gnikcuf os s’tI
.onnud I …tsuj I
,ecalp reippah a otni flesym eil ot gniyrt fo
?otni s’ehs gniht a tsuj s’ti fi tahW
,noitcurtsed nwo ruoy ni tnapicitrap gnilliw a eb ot gnitnaW ?on
:drawrofthgiarts os ton si sevlesruo nihtiw rorret eht taht ,syaw fo tsedrah eht ni ,nrael ot tuoba era srevol yrawnu owt tuB
dna  yppah gnieb otni flesym kcirt ll’I dna em peek nac ehs sa gnol sa rof ,gniht
.esiwrehto noitcnuf t’ndluow yehT
.tab eripmav laretil a m’I
,yako eb ot gniog m’I fi em ksa ro
,smra reh tsniaga ni gnizeeuqs fo dnik tsuj
tab ruoy gniksa enigami uoy dluoc
.reverof efil ym evael dna em etah reh ekam si od dluow reh gnitnorfnoc lla
,amard eht ,sgnaf eht ,epahs eht
ot gnihton ,tifeneb terces on yllaer s’erehT
,siht gniees eb t’nac I
.deneppah tahw tuoba flesym ot eil ot gniyrt
.skcuS .tI
…t’nod I ,traeh reh tae ,reh evas ,reh pots ot tnaw I ?suolaeJ
…leef I dna ,edih ot gniyrt s’ehs nworf eht ees I
.tsulrednaW fo flow ,neguuY yb dna
,sgniht eseht fo kniht ot syaw reihtlaeh eht wonk uoY
,ti tup ecno teop eht sa
.tniop eht s’taht
.der fo stuog kciht htiw hcir dnah reh ,reh was I dnA
,gnorw s’tahw reh ksa I
.tuoba elbaresim eb ot esle gnihtemos  dnif ot gniog tsuj m’I taht
,em etaretilbo ot reh deen I ,reh evarc I
,edaced a rof rehtegot gnivil neeb ev’ew
.thgir t’nsi siht tuB
.ecA fo kniht ot tahw wonk t’nod I
.yawyna reh rof eb ot gniog saw I tnemtnioppasid a tahw tuoba kniht ot gnivah reve erofeb eid ot hguone ykcul eb ll’I dna
,meht ni elbmert llams a leef nac I
,etib eht fo enon tub
.niaga gnivil m’I ekil leef I
.seirots rorroh eht ni  ekil naem I tub
,efas em peek ot hguone serac ehs taht dna
eh taht eciton dna yad txen eht fo dir tog reven I taht ppa eht nepo ll’I
”,htoB ro ,sgnileeF ruoY ,traeH ruoY taE“
,pu ti kcuf d’I .onnud I …I ,em sevol pu thgiarts tsuj ehs fi dog dna
esuaceb gniht a yas t’nac I dna enip I dna enip I
,ydob nwo ym otni gid
?dne eht siht si doG
,sdnarts kciht oN .yllattimmocnon
,hguorht gniog m’I tahw wonk ot sah ehs …ehS
?reh rof gnihtyreve eb ot ,reh tae ot deen I od yhW
.deb ni kcab s’ehs won dnA  –  …tnaw tsuj I
—  .gnorw gnihton eb dluohs erehT
,lla ti ot kaelb fo dnik gnihtemos tsuj s’ereht
,em sekil ehs fi rednow I ,htiw sdneirf m’I lrig siht htiw gnineppah s’tahw wonk t’nod I hO
,em tuoba serac ehs taht wonk I
,tuo reh ksa ,pihsnoitaler lamron a evah dluoc I ekil leef ot tnaw I
,tab eripmav a si ehs ,naem I
,pots tsuj ot retteb s’ti taht flesym gnillet no peek I
,enohp reh no reh ees I ,reh raen teg I
ecA htiw hcuot ni teg ot elba m’I nehw tub
kcol eW .hguone ylpmis deldnah si tuohtiw rorret ehT
,llew gniog era sgniht taht yppah eb dluohs I .sseug I .enif
?reh ta yrgna I mA .yrgnuh
,egru eht lleuq dna yrt dna dnah nwo ym tils em ees t’nac ehs os moor rehto eht ot ffo nur dna reh morf yawa llup ot evah I thgin yreve tuB
–  .em was ehs nehw oS
.gnignol dna doolb tsuj s’tI
.gnorw gnihtemos gniod si rentrap ruoy ekil leef ot gnitnaw ton tub
,dab si wonk uoy taht thguoht a evah uoy nehw sneppah tahW  –  .taht ksir naht
htob su revo lla ydob ym fo tuo depmup steg luos dna traeh yrev ym dna yretra rojam a skcin dna lortnoc sesol ehs taht thgin yreve yarp
,yad lla segassem mih sdnes ehS
.gnitavarggA .gnikcuF .os s’tI
.sniev reh ni gnimaercs doolb reh raeh yllacitcarp nac I ekil leef I
,evah nac I gnileef rehto yna syortsed ti taht yldab os taht tnaw ot reh tnaw I
.dneterp ot sah ehs ,tahw rettam oN
dna …dna won dna ereh yhW
.ti tuoba gnihtemos
.siht kniht yllautca t’nod uoY
?reve mih ot deklat yllaer ev’I kniht t’nod I ,kcis ylbirroh s’eH
,sgnileeF ruoY ,traeH ruoY taE“ saw sihT
.kcab llup I sa ecaf ym no enon s’ereht epoh I doG  –  -t’nac I
.eripmav a saw dneirf tseb ym hsiw I syademoS
,yako si siht taht dneterp dna rehtegot kcab ecaf ym tup ll’I dna
,erehwyreve nepo enohp ym evael I wonk I
,ylsseltroffe trapa flesti sleep ti
—  -esrow gnitteg peek smaerd eht ,eramthgin a
…niarb ruoy ni egats retnec ekat ot ereh tsuj si ti tey dna ,siht eveileb yllautca t’nod  uoY
?tihs suolucidir fo dnik taht
.gnorw si gnihton taht epoh tsuj
,smra ym ni ereh s’ehS
.nruter ni ygolopa lanoisacco eht htiw ,revo dna revo ,dnarts gnol a ni segassem reh tsuj si ppa regnessem ehT
,syaw suoivbo ,raelc
.gnihton rof tnaw I taht hguone yhtlaew s’ylimaf ym
.oot em seracs evol taht tub
eb ot meht rof dna kaerf a ton m’I taht hguone lamron htob eb sgnileef esoht evah dna leef I woh reh llet
,ruf tfos ,suoegrog ,seiceps yerP
,serised neddibrof
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.gnorw s’taht tuB
ecA gniretsep tuohtiw sruoh 42 naht erom og t’nac I
.krowkcolc ekil s’ti tub
…yas ot reh tnaw I dna
uoy taht thguoht a evah uoy nehw sneppah tahW  :ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  anueL yb ”htoB ro ,sgnileeF ruoY ,traeH ruoY
yllaer ehs fi tahW
taE“   yojne esaelP  ”.roiretni na
,yppah em ekam ot gniog reven s’ti ,sneppah taht fo lla fi neve
,doog leef em ekam neve t’nod yeht ,daeh ym ni sthguoht  eseht tnaw t’nod I ,gniht taht od
”yxes erew seripmav fi tahw“ fo evaw wen siht os
,ti fo citehtsea eht stnaw enoyrevE
.nosrep laer a ssel dna  ssel em ekam
.siht tnaw I taht wonk
.gnihtyna ees t’ndid ehs tahT
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.daetsni em esu ot gniggeb
thgin ta semitemoS
.aedi on evah I dna shtnom rof namow siht htiw deb a gnirahs neeb ev’I
.taorht ym ni traeh ym leef nac I .sgnaf reh ot ,spil reh ot gnignilc emos s’erehT
.kcart ffo m’I ,gnilarips m’I
…yllaretil ,yllautca ot tnaw t’nod I ,reh truh ot tnaw t’nod I
,sdnah reh gnihcuot diova I
?snaibsel sseleulc tuoba enilno ees uoy stsop ekoj diputs esoht wonk uoY
.si ti wonk uoy dna dab si gnikniht era uoy tahw ,ezilautxetnocer ot gnihton ,xif ro ezylana
.tniop on s’ereht wonk I tub
–  .reh was I nehw oS
.ecruos hserf a retfa enip dna em setas ti litnu doolb evarc ot
.ti gnikcol tuohtiw nwod ti stup ehs nehw ti no skeep kcuns ev’I
,sgniht eseht kniht ot gnorw s’ti wonk I  .t’nac
—  -peek nac I os won traeh ym llik ot evah I
,regguR .P .B yb daeR  .ytiniffAruF ta
.trapa gnillaf emoc lliw gnihtyreve ,gnihtyreve dna
.doolb nwo rieht otni yldriew era ohw elpoep wonk I
.doolb eht tegrof ot woh wonk t’nod I
,mih evael ot em llet dna em dloh ro
.I ?ees ehs did hcum woH
,kcis leef em ekam yeht
,reh evol I kniht I dna doof em syub ehs
,toh neeb syawla ev’yehT .evian sleef
,nooM ooM elbaffeni eht
—  -gnihton was I tahT
noitcif trohs laerrus gnitirw si dna ,tsiyasse na sa skrow ohw ,anueL yb
,od ot dengised m’I lla s’taht ebyaM
.siht ekil gnileef pots ot tnaw I ,tnaw I tahw wonk t’nod I .wonk t’nod I
.siht fo thgin rehtona eb ot gniog s’tI
?yppah em ekam taht t’nac yhw os
,krow siht ekam ot gniyrt fo thgin rehtonA
taht diarfa m’I tuB
,evil ot tnaw tsum I
naht tsohg lanretxe gniteem
?taht ssecorp neve I dluoC ?em sevol
—  -peelsa saw ehs thguoht I ,nees evah ot dah ehS
?siht ekil evol taht nruter neve I dluoC
.esrow leef uoy gnikam ylno s’ti
…reh eb ll’I taht dna ppa regnessem eht eteled ll’I esimorp  ll’I
.evil ot tnaw I taht flesym gnillet peek I
dna efink a barg
?em eb ti t’ndluoc yhW .deb ot kcab og
,sthguoht gnorw ynam os evah I
.esaelp ,reh esol t’nac I .t’nac tsuj I
.sklof rekcuf retsnom lausnesnoc ,yffulf eseht lla s’ti won tuB
ll’I dna ,mih ot seod ti sa em ot elttil sa snaem ti taht
—  -klat ot tnaw ton ehs seod yhW ?em tuohtiw
,thgindim a fo ,refas raF“
tub efil ym fo gnihtemos ekam ot em no gnidneped ylimaf a evah I
fo esoprup eht rof ylgnimees
,niarb ruoy otni ekips a gnivird s’ti ,lufplehnu ,yhtlaehnu s’tI
?taht ekil flesreh gnitruh ehs si yhW ?yhW
.gnitsuahxe tsuj s’ti yltsenoH .ylsuoivbO
,esrow dna esrow sgniht ekam ot gniog ylno era wonk I taht stnaw elbirroh ynam os
.gnorw s’gnihton taht eb ot sah rewsna ehT
,reh tsniaga ni flesym yrub ot gniyrt
,lrig hcir a htiw gnivil m’I ,gnikrow m’I
.taht eb t’nac I wonk I dna
…tsuj si gnihtyrevE .t’nseod ehs tub
?dneirfyob a sah fo dnik …llits ehS
,gnidnuop doolb ym leef nac I
dlohserht eht gnitlas sa hcus slautir
—  -esaelp gnihtyreve ,gnihtyna ,kcab lla ti ekat I ,reh esol ot tnaw t’nod I
dna seenk dna sdnah ym no flesym gniworht gnikcuf ton dnats t’nac tsomla I tahT
.siht ekil eb ot sdeen ti ,oN
,em gnola pu gnippils s’ehS
.tuoba klat ot sah eh tahw erac neve t’nod I
.ecaf reh ta gnikool ksir neve t’nac I  —  .ecaf ym no doolb s’ereht fi dog ,nepo tuc mlap ,em neeS
.goD fo ecioV eht no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.kcolB eht ffo enohp reh worht ll’ew dna sey yas tsuj ll’ehs taht sgnileef fo dnik thgir eht tsuj
,yrossecca nA ?huh
.tsirw reh nwod ylgnizilatnat tsomla gninnur ti ees I
ynam os ni gnorw si tnaw I tahW .ecaf ot gnihtoN
dna efil ym ni ecno rof lufesu leef ll’I dna knik doolb a sah ehs taht timda ll’ehs ebyam dna
…tsuj era sgniht eseht taht ,gnileef eb dluohs uoy woh ,gniod eb dluohs uoy tahw wonk uoy
,derit elttil a tsuj ,enif m’I
.elpmis tub ,evitceffe lla ton spahreP
…tsuj dna ereht kcab teg dna pu naelc ot deen I ,evila pihsdneirf ruo peek nac I oS
reh llet dna skceB ta elims ot evah ll’I neht dnA
,toidi na m’I em lleT .gnihtynA
,ekawa depmuj dna peelsa saw I
.ees t’ndid ehs lleh ni yaw on s’erehT
.guns dnuora gnipparw smra reh