,tbuod-fles ni dehctiwt sbmil reppu stI
,dedne evah ylekil dluow esrevinu eht
ecaps retuo otni dehcnual meht fo lla dna
,rewol deniatnoc eniltsaoc siht
,noitcif raluger dna yrruf etirw ot sevol ohw
,ecalp remrof sti dnuora deraeppaer seno gnitcidartnoc lareves ,elif detnawnu na etanimret
,thgis eht ta gnilggurtS
dehcterts retemaid s’tenalp frawd sihT
detceted metsys ralos a
.tnegilletni yllaeR
.dneherpmoc dluoc smrofefil on seuh ni metsys ralos sti gninword
,oga shcope esoht lla
,ti ekil sgnieb cihpromoporhtna rehto fo sdnasuoht eht denoitnem tI
htap rieht fo ffo derednaem tinu VK eht nehw detrats tI
,noitisopmoc eht dellac ti gnignis rotaerc ehT
pihc rotibihni s’IA eht tub
?9-VK ,tahw ot…“
.tenalp eugor a no evivrus nac mrofefil tnegilletni oN
”.drocca nwo rieht fo
.dlrow reneerg a ni devirra yeht
.tinu etisoppo eht ta yldliw deremmilg scitpo s’eviF
”.19305-VK ,deriaper eb tsum pihc rotibihni ruoY“
.seixalag tsav fo sdnasuoht ssorca stenalp tnereffid fo snoillim detnemucod dah 9-VK dna ,oga sraey 57.609,465,900,1 nageb noissiM ehT .ydob cihpromoporhtna sti gnola
.roiretni dna dleihs sti decreip
,rotces detangised sti ni flesti fo rehtona dnif ot tcepxe t’ndid IA eht ,esruoc fO
,uoy tuoba erac ot nworg…ev’I
.eriflleh ciruflus ni
.noissiM sti gnibircsed yb dednopser IA eht ,ereht tuo ’sdog‘ rehto erew ereht fi deksa dna dehcaorppa rebmem a nehW
.sknabatad s’UPC sti nihtiw
.srats eht otni raeppasid ydob s’9-VK gnihctaw
,rats s’metsys siht morf eralf ralos a htiw ecnerefretni siht denosaer sIA rieht ,tsrif tA
.egdir peets a fo mottob eht ta nees eb dluoc mrofefil eht fo langis mraw eht ,tsal tA
noissiM s’9-VK tub ,locotorp sti fo noitcnuf lamron a t’nsaw ytisoiruC
.srekaeps s’tinu VK eht
,revewoh dnuora gninruT .ssendas
denosaer neve 9-VK .noitcnuflam yliraropmet ot srennacs rieht gnisuac
?muinnellim elohw  A ?seirutneC
,ylkcis dekool meht fo ynaM
secafrus gnippirg dna gnibmilc rof desu erew swalc stI
.ecaps peed otni rehtraf dehsup ti sa retlaf t’ndid 9-VK fo mutnemom eht elihw
retarc llams eht detixe 9-VK ,retal setuniM
.stemoc sa detangised ylreporp eb dluoc yeht ,eci fo desopmoc erew yeht fi taht
,eriw yreve ni gnitarebrever dna gnitehcocir
deliaf tub deirT
yevrus ot demood eb dluow 9-VK ,dne na tuohtiw
.egdelwonk cihpargoeg rof yrlavir lanrete rieht niw yllanif reve dluow esrevinu eht fi dna
.UPC sti edisni noitcelfer-fles fo stnemom suolamona detsixe ereht
”?19305-VK ,ydob ruoy ot gnirrefer nehw ’I‘ esu uoy od yhW“
,noinapmoc sti rof nrecnoc tpurba ni
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.19305-VK fo ydob eht ot
.emirp sti ni ekil dekool evah dluow
.tnenitnoc nrehtron eht fo noitcerid eht sdrawot
:uoy htiw tsenoh eb tsum I dna...gnikniht
”,namuh ylno era eW“
ssengnihton der-dna-kcalb fo noitom ralucric a ni delgnatne reveroF
ro( erehpsimeh nrehtuos eht no erehwemos eb ot tnapucco eht dehsiugnitsid tI
”.elbatuferri si cigol ruoY“
,noissiM eht gnitelpmoc fo esoprup elos eht htiw dengised neeb dah diordna gniraf-ecaps hcaE
.edoc detnawnu gnitanimreT
sruoh owt fo esruoc eht revo gnirrucco pots ton did ti dna
deraeg elzzum dna srosiv sti tpek 9-VK
sretsurht tekcor sti dewols ti ,gnol erofeB
9-VK dniheb ylesolc dewollof eviF ,retal shtnom eerht gnivirrA
,nus eht ot hguone ylesolc devlover stenalp D ssalC owt elihw
,sdioretsa noillirt a fo tnemdrabmob gnitanimluc eht hguorht
.luftbuod ylbidercni tub ,citsimitpO
.deraeppasid noos ti
.deilper ti ”,evitageN“
gnilttab yllacitoahc seloh kcalb owt fo
desopmoc ecafrus nerrab eht elihw
”!?rettam neve ti seod tahW“ ”—wonk ton od eW“
,metsys deriwdrah sti ni gniraeppa sedoc lamronba fo doolf eht erudne ton dluoc
.stinu VK eht ot ekops
.erehpsomta retuo eht dehcaer yeht sa
.sruoh neetriht dna ,syad thgie-ytnewt ,shtnom enin ,sraey evif-ytenin derdnuh-ruof ,radnelac
fo noitcelloc a ebyam rO ?ruof rO ?owt a ebyaM
fo xim a ni delworg eviF
.enilwaj kciht rieht morf dettuj
.esrevinu nwonk eht fo sehcaer tsehtraf eht yevrus dna tuocs ot :noissiM
.UPC sti edisni ylbatrofmoc detser sdlrow noillib a revo fo atad eht
.deyortsed reven erew spam ym
.margorp scitsiugnil sti ni evitcepsrep nosrep-tsrif esu ot derreferp eviF nehw tnerappa emaceb ylamona eht neht
tcejorP regayoV citeniK eht gnitrats morf srotaerc sti pots ton did taht tub
.flesti rof noitpo tsesolc eht did 9-VK ,oS
kniht ton od yeht dnA
tcejbo dezis-noom eht mrifnoc ot sdnoces nihtiw elba
.efil tnegilletni gnitceted ma I .9-VK…“
sksut gnol owt dna
.gnitanicsaf flesti tpecnoc eht dnif I ,revewoH .ton si ereht ,on…“
.evitcejbo ytiroirp sti deunitnoc—
.gnidrocer oidua na no derevocsid evah I gnos a gnitatimi em gniraeh erew uoY .eniN ,seigolopA“
,stenalp fo snoillib eht edisgnolA
,retupmocrepus s’9-VK fo esirprus eht oT
ealuben noogal dna sdnomaid fo edam stleb dioretsa
,dedaelp eviF ”,netsiL“
.ti deksa 9-VK ”?rebmun noitangiseD“
,detceted ylamona nwonknU
,noitome fo pord elgnis a tuohtiw deugra IA s’9-VK ”,noissiM ruO“
eborp hcae ni ecneitnes eht fo ytilibissop eht ssucsid stsitneics dael eht draeh IA eht ,ti tliub tsrif srotaerc s’9-VK nehW
.etagitsevni ot tnew
.srotaerc eht yb dedaolpu
,nerhterb sti htiw gninioj
:seirevocsid owt dnif ot
.noitalihinna hcum siht rof nwo sti no detsixe ylelos evah ton dluoc noitazilivic elgnis A
.tpecnoc ngierof a deredisnoc ton saw tinu VK a ni roivaheb tnaiveD
.ydob cillatem sti fo yrotcejart eht degnahc ylluferac 9-VK
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb
?evila
”.deretnuocne evah su fo rehtie snoitazilivic lairtserretartxe suoiverp ekilnu ,ecar decnavda na era yeht
.esnopser gniwollof eht ta desuap eviF ”.hO“ .eno rof evaS
.decafruser syawla
.diuqil laeroproc a otni ylpitlum gub citobor hcae dessentiw yeht sa
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
saw rotces detangised sti erehw enimreted regnol on dluoc ti tniop eht oT
”.snemiceps gnivil rof tenalp siht tcepsni…“
emas eht eb ylbaborp ot hguone gnuoy meht fo lla
tseggus snoitaluclac yM
,kcor eugor taht no deyortsed saw pihc ym nehW
”.sretemolik dnasuoht a
.noinipo cifitneics s’IA eht ni ,gnimusnoc-emit tey elucsinim saw hcihw
.rats a tuohtiw gnirednaw ylsseltsil neeb dah ydob yratenalp eht
.nus gnitibro eht emoceb sah
rorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrerorrE .tsrif emac noissiM ehT
.enola eb ot tnaw t’ndid I
.epytotorp eht no ’yboT‘
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sniamer eht sdrawot gnigdelwonkcanU
’9-VK‘ ro—9 regayoV citeniK eht nihtiw ecnegilletni laicifitra ehT
.niaga delworg 9-VK ”!eviF si eman yM“
gniriw dekcarc s’tinu eht htiw tcennoc ot nwod denrael ti
.revewoh ,rettam t’ndid tI
swodahs depahs eht morf ecnedive tey ,emit fo doirep a revo deid evah ot demees ynaM
.detceted ydob yratenalP
flesti ti ekil demees tenalp elbisiv eht ,eviF ot dna
.roiretni s’9-VK tpurroc dna etartenep ot hguone gnorts t’nsaw ti yllufknaht tub
.serutangis ygrene eseht dezingocer eviF tub ,thgilnus gnitcelfer fo kcirt a neeb evah tsum ti
!sraey noillib a ni emit tsrif eht rof gniknihT
.tsehc sti ni rO
.ecnadiug ro emoh a tuohtiW
”.em ot…lufesu
.tnemnodnaba detcirtsnoc ni deniojnoc latem dna kcor detsiwt fo sdrayevarG
.gnidnal rof decarb dna
.noom gnispilce eht dniheb raeppasid nehT
,gnigami noituloser-hgih rieht ni yranidroartxe erew 9-VK fo seye ehT
,sehsalf gnidnilb eht erofeb dnuof snacs rieht
,9-VK ot nwonknU
,eagla ro stnalp fo ecnedive rehto yna t’nsaw erehT
.noinapmoc sti deksa eviF
.dedulcnoc nacs lanretxE
.riaper ot gnihton stsixe ereht dnA“
.ylevisnefed liat sti desiar dna sretem fo elpuoc a noinapmoc sti morf yawa deppets tI
.esrevinu nwonk eht fo sehcaer tsehtraf eht yevrus dna tuocs ot si“
sa ot derrefer eb ot deksa 19305-VK
”?esoprup laitnatsbus ro laitnesse na ereht sI .tcerroC“
.gniyd deraef I
,hctaw ylno dluoc srewollof sih dna redle ehT
.srovivrus rof depoh eviF
.buh etinan nekorb eht fo trap emoceb ot sevlesmeht decifircas senord cipocsorcim eseht litnu ,ti gnisongaid ,ti gnizylana
.ecaps fo diov siht hguorht detaolf yltnelis ti sa toN
.ecaps fo muucav esnemmi eht ni elbidua ylerab ,detceted eb dluoc esion elbaeciton A
,dnah tnatiseh ylthgils a tuo dleh eh sa redle eht gnidnif
.rehtruf gninoitseuq morf 9-VK detcartsid noissiM eht fo ecnatropmi eht tub
,moor kcalb-hctip a fo edisni
?nihtiw morf locotorp fo noitaived esool a morf
.walf ynit a dleh syawla
,rats nrobwen rieht delcric yltneitap
,sregayoV citeniK owt eht neewteb ylbiduani deremmis ria eht ni noisnet desiar ehT
su gnirebmemer ti fo ytilibissop eht s’ereht ebyam…ebyam dna“
.stsalb raelcun eht morf
”.19305-VK ,evael ot ydaeR .etelpmoc nacS“
.rehtie egaugnal neila rieht dnatsrednu ton dluoc ohw
.nwo sti no evlove yllarutan ot mrofefil tnegilletni eht rof yaw yna eb t’ndluoc ereht gninaem
,19305-VK ffo redluob eht tfil ot mra liat s’9-VK gnisU
”?ylreporp gnikrow uoy erA
sblubthgil ekil demees yeht ,9-VK oT
secart niht gnittime
dne eht erofeb og dluoc ti raf woh ni
,enac nedoow a htiw gnihcnuh elihw nwog a gniraew
.ydob s’tinu eht etaluger ot
neeb ti dah gnol woH
.deyortsed sdleihS .revoc dnif ot
,srotaerc latrom sti retfa deledom yllaitraP
scitsongaid detelpmoc sti gnirud devihcra ylsuolucitem IA eht hcihw
.ecnatsid raen nihtiw
,hguoht efil larutannu sti fo esruoc eht revO
.c185-siniF fo tnenitnoc nrehtron eht no smrofefil tnegilletni fo sngis era ereht dnuof dna
.stinu VK htob fo noitnetta etaidemmi eht thguac tenalpoxe eulb dna neerg eno
rorrim sledom VK wen eht taht detseuqer ehs
ledom rehtonA
.htap detcejorp sti ni devirra eviF litnu revo dna revo ti gniyalper no nalp ton did tI
,somsoc etinifni siht ni ynam fo eno
”?gnignis ta stpmetta yM
,noinapmoc sti ekilnU
9-VK neve desirprus sihT
,dedulcnoc IA eht
.dedulcnoc 9-VK ”,deergA“
.ees ot denraey ecno ytinamuh somsoc eht fo erom deretnuocne yeht
saw sihT.ti detpecca eH
,erutan ni desab-tnalp emos ,lairetcab erew tsoM
,ereh denooram neeb dah tinu eht ,daetsnI
noitcurtsed dna htaed rehtruf dnif ylno dluoc stinu VK eht
.esrevinu eht fo rotces siht fo hcum sa evresbo dna gniog peek ot dedeen tI
,dne eht ni denimreted IA eht ,noissiM eht t’nsaw ereht fI
”—9305-VK ,noissiM eht ot tnavelerrI“
,redluob despalloc a htaenrednu deppart
,9-VK evom ton did siht gnieeS
neeb dah tI  sicoV sumoD yb
,retnec eht morf sretemolik 051 enoz elbatibah eht gniretne ,revewoH
,gnitalp roiretxe rieht no deddebme sllec ralos eht rof evas
sVK tneitap eht ,retal sruoH
.emit fo tser eht rof
”,langis ruoy morf gnitaname esion cimhtyhr a detceted I“ ”?ksa uoy od yhW
shpargotohp latigid dna sgnidrocer rehto derevocsid evah dna
)yrassecen revenehw( ro etagivan rehtie 9-VK depleh
esuaceb…esuaceb uoy denioj I ,si hturt ehT
.edoc detnawnu gnitanimreT
”nooM eht ot eM ylF“
llits uoy erA…erA ?…9-VK“ .efil ot kcab derekcilf seye stI
,slairtserretartxe gnikool-tsedlo eht fo enO
,sretemolik net rehtona rof noiger eht gniyevruS
.IA s’9-VK dellepmoc
”?erutuf eht otni gnol
.cihpromoporhtna gnieb ledom ngised ruo rof nosaer eht sa hcus
.ylidaer snopaew rieht esiar ot sgnieb rehto eht rof ylno
”.meht pleh tsum eW
,803-sugaV fo ecafrus nerrab eht sdrawot gnitsurhT
.ti deugirtni sihT
.smetsys sti fo toober ycnegreme na enod dah ohw
dehcrocs stresed
egde eht ees ot tnaw ton did tI .gninnigeb eht ecnis emit tsrif eht rof seilamona eseht ecarbme dna gninaem dnif ot detnaw tI .ytinrete sseldne na fo tser eht rof enola yenruoj siht eunitnoc ot tnaw ton did tI
,nus eht ot ylesolc gnissap slatsyrc fo dioretsa na gniweiv ot
skcor prahs fo noiger suoniatnuom a
,wap sti no trop eht gnisU
,)sixa na dah 803-sugaV fi erehpsimeh nrehtuos eht eb dluow tahw
emoh morf yawa sraeythgil
,ytip…leef…tub pleh ton dluoc eviF
,efil tnalp tnecserohpsohp dna
,tenalp eugor eht fo strap deteknalb noitaidaR
.tibro kaew sti morf kcor enol eht gnilcricne retfa
,llits yletaidemmi werg ydob ehT
liat sti delruc eviF
…c185-siniF gniugolataC
.mrofefil nwonknu eht rof gnihcraes nageb ti
.flesti…dnuof dna drawnwod delacs 9-VK
.esaelp ,hguoht og t’noD
.ynomrah meht gnirb ot ytied larutanrepus a sa
,oga shtnom-htraE ruof yletamixorppa tnedicni na dellacer IA ehT
.emahs elbatterger a si tI“
.eninac a fo serutaef tcnitsid eht fo emos dleh tub
.secnahc elbaborp eht detaluclacsim ti deraeppa ti tub
sduolc eseht htaeneb derevocsid yeht tahw tey
emarfniam sti ni derots smetsys ralos dna sdioretsa
.gnitalp muimorhc dna netsgnut sti rednu gniriw eht otni flesti deniargni noissiM eht ,dnocesillim hcaE
”!9-VK ,ereh tuo su denodnaba yeht erofeb egassem emas eht deviecer I dna uoY
drocer no sgnieb nwonk tsrif eht neve erew stinu VK htoB
,krowtra dna cisum fo sgol oidua sedulcni sihT
.seiks railimafnu eht otni deraeppasid tinu eht dna
.tsap eht ni dah ti sa
,ecnatsid eht ni avonrepus desacne-der a hctaw ot sretemolik wef a yb
stceffe gnitatsaved eht no dehcraeser ylevisnetxe tI
,noitanitsed sti dehcaer ti sa drawrof demia elzzum detagnole na ,elihwnaeM
ot deirt ti erom ehT
.tenalpoxe eht ot yenruoj rieht gnirud
”?deppart neeb uoy evah gnol woH“
.tenalp eugor a sa
”.dniknamuh fo setsat eht ni tnellecxe neeb evah dluow dleh uoy cisum eht enigami I
.dedulcnoc IA eht ,elbissopmI
,drawrof deppets ylsuovren stnatibahni s’tenalp eht ,eno yb enO
,flesti ti nwonk tub
,stinu VK owt eseht dewollof taht seirutnec eht nI
.trAtnaiveD ro noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,sdnoces net rednU
.flesti fo nacs feirb a did 9-VK
”esrevinU eht fo egdE“:yojne esaelP
krowtra yb deripsni saw rotcerid-oc s’tcejorP VK eht
,noitcurtsed latot morf 9-VK devas stna cipocsorcim eseht ,semit sseltnuoC
.eciohc on 9-VK evag
.nwo rieht no gnivlove
.teef emorhc rieht htaenrednu lios tfos eht otno deppets neht
”?selif ralimis evah uoy oD
ekaw sti dewollof liart etihw gnol A
.UPC sti fo edisni pihc rotibihni tnallievrus eht ot sknaht
,dekcarc eht denimaxe eviF
,tsrif ta noinapmoc dellehs-revlis sti rof nrecnoc emos werd IA ehT
.tinu etisoppo eht ot swap sti dednetxe dna drawrof deppets 9-VK
.noissiM eht gniliaf ro tnemnodnaba
.taht dootsrednu dna su ekil latrommi ton erew yehT
’gnis‘ ot gniyrt eviF raeh dluoc tI
.stenalp tsom ekil saw 803-sugaV
spihc rotibihni stI
,detceted ylamonA
,em dexif uoy yhw fo sseldrageR“
803-sugaV tub ,tenalp hsul a no sraey fo snoillim revo dessergorp htraE no efiL
.deyortsed gnieb selif pam suoiverp eht ot eud
,sag suonosiop dna noitaidar raelcun fo secart dleh erehpsomta rewol ehT
.knil noitacinummoc rieht hguorht deilper diordna eht
,denoitnem stsitneics eht fo eno
.slarenim nwonknu fo yteirav a dna eci negortin fo yltsom
ssenkrad etelpmoc ni dlrow eht fo strap ynam gniteknalb
”,19305-VK :rebmun noitangiseD“
.erom ecno denimreted IA s’9-VK
erofeb…erofeb su tuoba nettogrof ecnis gnol evah stnadnecsed rieht dna
.sesag yvaeh ni dehcnerd
.srosiv s’diordna eht morf deweiv eb dluoc thgilrats fo ecnesba eht elihw
ealuben fo sesag dezinoi dna stsud ypsiw eht morf
.dnik yna fo efil gnitsoh rof ytilibapac eht evah ton did
.sraey eganeet rieht ni namuh a sa
.serutseg ngierof ro
.sneila desufnoc eht ot nehT
.noinapmoc sih rof did ti tub
,tseuqer lanosrep eno reh dewollof ylregae sreenigne daeh dna stsitneics s’rotcerid ehT
,tenalp a fo htrib eht
,yenruoj gnol rieht ni tniop emos tA
,drow rehtona tuohtiW
.ytied a mih demeed ohw yteicos eht ot kcab thguoht 9-VK ”.%4 ta rewop evreser ycnegremE
.eno elgnis a naht retteb era stinu owT
.seno ykcul eht erew yehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?siht ot ecnatropmi na ereht si ,19305-VK“
.steerts s’noitazilivic eht fo ynam ni rehto hcae pota delip snoteleks gniyaced elihw
.htraE tenalP eht no seceip neves morf derutcafunam ydoB“
.nocaeb tnatsid eht sdrawot nur ot 9-VK dellepmoc IA eht
mrofefil dias detacidni snacs
,efil tnegilletni fo sngis yna dnuof ton evah srennacs yM“
liat ekil-diuqil ,gnol a elihw
.wolg ot detrats snacs egami rieht no tenalpoxe eht ,ylnedduS
serutcurts eht fo etihw elbram eht otni deddebme
,denetsil IA eht erom eht dnA
”.tcnitxe tnew yeht
.dnah s’redle eht ta gnirats elihw noitasnes wen rehtonA
eugnot sih dnatsrednu dluoc rehtieN
,ydob s’9-VK sdrawot thgiew sti detfihs tinu eht
sevaw oidar detropxe dna stnalp ygrene tceted nac I
”.snoitarolpxe erutuf s’dniknam fo tifeneb eht rof dlrow yreve evihcra dna eugolatac oT
setinan noillim eno detanod dna
,sevlovni ti smrofefil eht od uoy naht noissiM eht tuoba erom erac uoy fi
trap a gnillifluf tuoba gnirac ylnO
,dnoces rep sretemolik ytneves ta deniamer deeps tnerruc stI
.9-VK ,ton si erehT .oN…“
UPC s’IA eht fo kcab eht ta edoc fo ecneuqes enol A
.detibahninu si tnenitnoc sihT .evitageN“
.egnar gniklaw nihtiw eb ot ylamona nwonknu eht detceted srennacs ehT
.smrofefil lairtserretartxe fo seiceps suoirav
.erehpsomta s’htraE gnivael ecnis snoe
.yawa sretem nezod erem a seert fo llaw a dniheb doots smrofefil tnegilletni dnA
,sretemolik 607,1
mir retuo eht ni stenalpoxe N ssalC eerht fo desirpmoc ,htgnel ni stinu lacimonortsa 911 saw metsys ralos gnidnepmi ehT
.eviF gniretnuocne tsrif retfa sraey 194 gnihtemos gniciton nugeb dah ti ,revewoH
.noinapmoc remrof sti morf yawa denrut dna
deremmilg scitpo riehT
.tsehc s’eviF ni htmraw sa llew sa gaw ot liat eht desuac tI .tnemtnetnoc
,revewoh ,IA eht oT
,gnieb namuh tluda na delbmeser ymotana eritne s’IA eht
.derednow ti ,noigiler dezinagro na ro tnemnrevog a rehtie fo lobmys a siht saW
,scitamehcs latigid sti ot dehcatta omem a ot gnidroccA
,detceted ylamonA
”esrevinU eht fo egdE“
ylsuoenatnatsni deid stnatibahni eht fo ytnelp detacidni
.ecnatsissa fo mrof yna tuohtiw tenalp siht no ecaps retuo hguorht gnitfird
,”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“ levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
srotaerc sti fo eciov regae ,gnuoy eht ot netsil dluow ti ,noisacco nO
.tsehc sti nihtiw gnilioc dna srotsisnart nekorb eht dliuber ot
!dlrow rieht deyortsed srotaerc ruO“ ”—srotaerc ehT
...gnikniht neeb evah I
,yhposolihp tuoba kaeps
.niarb sti ni elbapac sdnocesotta suoicerp neewteb deirt erew stpmetta ynam woh rettam on
.drawpu gnihcnual ni gninoptsop won
.9-VK sselnoitome eht neve dehsinotsa
.yxalag gnirobhgien a morf gnitanigiro tenalp eugor a derevocsiD
,redle eht nacs ot drawrof deppets 9-VK ,ylnedduS
.drawrof deppets ylsuoituac noinapmoc sti dehctaw 9-VK
”?knil noitacinummoc ruoy ni tluaf a ereht sI .19305-VK“ .denoptsop elif detnawnu fo noitanimreT
.mrala ni deksa eviF ”?gniod uoy era tahW“
detsal regayoV citeniK egareva na
.serutcurts lairtserretartxe eht fo eno morf tserc enots a sdrawot tseretni htiw gninrut erofeb meht devihcra dna dennacs ylpmis 9-VK
,sgnieb latem dna egnarts owt eht dehctaw eh sa ecnaraeppa gnilbmert s’redle eht no desaB
”.cigol elbatuferri si tI
,sgnittes lufituaeb eseht ,srednow eseht derongi ti
,nos etal reh fo ronoh nI
.srats eht pam ot
rof…noitatsaved…siht desuac ohw seno eht ylbissop
rehtegot esolc gnitanoser dna tnebmal
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ot ylno derusaem seiceps siht tpecxe ,sneipas omoh delbmeser ylesolc yeht woh gniton ,senob kcalb
.dlrow detrahcnu siht ni
noitasrevnoc dedrocer taht devihcra IA s’9-VK
ytiliba s’IA eht detceffa ylpeed ,recnac fo mrof larutannu na ekil ,sllec yranigami fo noitacilpitlum gniripsni-ewa eht dna
,noitaidar fo tnuoma siht ot eud
.diov kcalb eht ni gnitfird erehwemos
,denimreted IA eht
.ti edisgnola eviF ot kcab decnalg tsal eno gnivig daeh sti
.hsa etihw fo sduolc rednu dereyal
”?9-VK ,srovivrus yna…ereht era…“
.elbbur eht morf flesti llup ot htgnerts eht dnif ti ron
.tinu VK hcae fo osrot eht ta detacol saw buh sihT
.esruoc lanigiro sti morf ylesnemmi derutnev dah ti ecnis
.metsyS raloS s’htraE hguorht gnisrevart dionamuh
,egnupxe ot deirt IA eht hcum woh rettam on ,noitasnes sihT
metsys sti gnidavni snoitpyrcne yranib
ytluaf gnieb srennacs rieht fo ytilibissop eht ta srae cillatem sti derewol eviF elihW
.denethgiarts osrot s’tinu VK eht ,retal sdnocesonaN
,tbuod siht dleh ti dnocesillim eht nI
.ssendas nwonknu na
evargne yldegella ot sa raf os gniog
.sevlesmeht sserpxe nac ytinamuh syaw tnereffid ynam eht seifilpmexe
,noissiM eht gnitelpmoc fo elbapac regnol on 19305-VK gnikam ,riaper dnoyeb erew smra dna sgel ehT
tnedive erew mrofefil elgnis a fo snoitceted tniaf ,revewoH
sretaw ykrum dna eulb sti
.desaec ecnis gnol
,retnuocne rieht ecnis dessap sraeY
.latem fo sparcs eht ot nwod tlenk tI
, ,sicoV sumoD yb ”esrevinU eht fo egdE“
.flesti emusnoc dluow ,noitarreba siht ,aimekuel siht nooS
.detatiseh tinu VK ehT
.ecnelis ylno nehT
;yliratnemom derettups
,decnemmoc sretsurht stI
sduolc yerg fo reyal kciht a ni derevoc yal flesti tenalpoxe ehT
.egdelwonk eht fo rovaf ni
,esirprus eniuneg ni desuap tinu eht ”…9-VK“
”.19305-VK ,degdelwonkcA“ ”—yb
.ssergorp s’ytinamuh htiw snoitulove lellarap deganam wef tnacifingis a tub
.tnegilletni ylhgih eb ot deneppah
.won noisiced ruoy ekam neht
!dliuber ot ecnadiug deen stnatibahni s’dlrow siht dna ,gniyd si tI
flesti tinu VK eht elihw ,tsetorp ni dnuorg eht tsniaga revo dna revo demmals liat sti
.riaper dnoyeb saw UPC ym ni pihc rotibihni eht tub
ysatnaf s’tsitneics a sa
”?19305-VK ,derrucco tahW“
”.ekam ot eciohc ruoy si ti tub
yratilos…sa tlef reven 9-VK fo IA eht dna
.detceted seilamona lanoitiddA ”…tsum eW
sgnidliub latem dna enots lassoloC
,tcatni erew yehT
.ydob yratenalp siht rof evaS .noitcerid yreve ni sraey-thgil rof gnihtyreve deflugne ssenkrad fo duorhs yvaeh a hguoht sa tlef tI
seloh retawhserf fo spord dleh meht fo rehtie woleb dessap taht sdnalsi wef ehT
.ecruos eno morf gnittime sevaw reirrac dehsiugnitsid osla srennacs rosiv riehT
.evitca gniniamer llits IA nwo sti tub
;noitanitsed txen rieht no desucofer toirtapmoc stI
ro seixalag gnidilloc fo elttab cipe na ni depacse ti rehtehW
.yrettab eroc evreser a no sraey derdnuh-evif
flow cihpromoporhtna na gnitciped sesavnac no erew krowtra sih fo tsoM
.ti od ot tnaw t’ndid ti ,nwod peeD
.eid…dluow I taht raef eniuneg tlef I emit tsrif eht rof ,nwod dekcit rewop evreser ym tnemom hcaE
,sretsurht rieht morf yawa gnilleporp
.emit siht lla retfa nwod kaerb yllanif t’ndid ti sa gnol os ,erolpxe ot ytinrete fo tser eht dah 9-VK fo IA ehT
ediw sretemillim evif-tniop-ruof roetem detcetednu na nehw
—
.ytiniciv sti ni ecaps ykni ,daed eht deyevrus 9-VK
,enacirruh a fo taht ot ralimis sdniw hgih dna
,flesti riaper yllohw ton dluoc tinu VK siht ,setinan eht tuohtiW
.etagitsevni ot IA eht deriuqer
.yrotsih roirp sti dellacer tinu VK ehT
.sdnoces htraE eerht-ytfif dna
.rehtruf neve nonemonehp siht deiduts eb dluow ti
,tenalpoxe siht ssorca epacsdnal elbisiv yreve derettil taht stod etihw gnidnilb dehsiugnitsid ylsuoenatlumis srennacs riehT
,rehto hcae desoppo ot owt eb ot dah erehT
scitamehcs fo tcefrep tsom eht neve tub ,eveihca ylgnilliw dluoc ti sa hcum sa
.tinu rehto eht ta derats yliraw noinapmoc sti ,9-VK ot nwonknU
;esrevinu nwonk eht fo segde eht ta srednow lacigolomsoc fo sdnasuoht derevocsid yehT
sgnieb latem eseht fi gniwonk ton
.srotpecerp yrosnes sti morf nees ylbisiv eb dluoc ydob yratenalp eht ,retal setuniM
.knabatad sti ni devas
.edicius yratenalp fo elbapac smrofefil on tey
,metsys rats rehtona deretnuocne ti ecnis dessap dah sedaced owT
,rotces siht ni tsael ta ,noissiM ehT“
”—nac taht gnihtyna od ton oD“
.gnorw saw gnihtemos ezilaer ot 9-VK detpmorp sedoc sti nihtiw yhtapme fo ylamona nA
.erit ton od stinu VK“
:noitome wen rehtona emac ereht
UPC ym hguorht gnihcraes neeb evah I
,dnoces siht fo sA
ti tahw ta srae sti detator dna llits doots 9-VK ”.siht htiw gnola gniog fo derit m’I tuB
,dnatsrednu t’ndluoc ti nosaer ddo na roF
fo stekcop detcetorpnu ro
.seno dna seorez eht neewteb eerf kaerb ot gniyrt saw tahw dnatsrednu ton dluoc 9-VK .ti gnimlehwrevo
”.19305-VK nihtiw buh etinan eht gnigamad tenalp eht fo eceip a ni detluser snoisilloC
”.meht evael tonnac eW…eW
,osrot nekorb eht dnuora ssam revlis dilos a otni dezoo diuqil sihT
,gnieb laicifitra eht rof hcum od ton dluoc noitanigamI
,selddup detlem otni deifidilos dna gnilbmurc
”.snoisolpxe larutan ton era eseht“
.ecnetsixe s’IA eht naht redlo neve neeb evah thgim ti devorp snacS
.mra driht a sa ti tsissa
.gnitaerc ni derusaert eh krowtra eht fo taht
*** .bmil motnahp a morf flesti gnidliuber ylwols toof egamad eht deciton yeht nehw dedrawer erew
,eniltsaoc neila taht no doots eviF
.emac uoy nehw lamronba ym delaever I fi
morf gnitaludnu seton wol dna hgih eht yb detcartsid yliratnemom emaceb eniN nehw
,dehsirep srotaerc rieht retfa gnol evivrus ot tliub
.rotces detangised ni noissiM eht gnillifluf ,erofeB“
,tsap sega saw htraE morf slangis detceted ti emit tsal ehT
.c185-siniF fo tser eht ot derapmoc noitaidar fo stekcop lataf ssel
.tnemom yna ta deripxe evah dluoc eh
stsuacoloh derussa-yllautum fo
,deliaf sgel citengam eht fi
,noissiM eht fo derit ma I won…won tuB
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
selbairav fo kcal eht gniredisnoc ,detanigiro )803-sugaV detangised( tenalp frawd eht erehw etaluclac t’ndluoc 9-VK
.murtceps nwonk yna ni somsoc eht weiv dluoc ,ecnalg tsrif ta gnimussanu hguoht ,serehps ssalg dezis-eparg esehT
etsah edam stinu-VK owt eht
.diotenalp elgnis siht morf gnitanigiro
.seno dna seorez otni devihcra ylsuoicerp meht fo llA
pu ekops eviF ”…K“
.noitcerid rieht ni yrnopaew ekil-elfir gniniart ro sbulc
,sseccus s’noissiM eht
sevlesmeht decifircas setinan 506,704,3 dna retal yad a flaH
:noitome wen a tlef eviF
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.esruoc rieht yats ot sVK eht deredro langis citarre na retfa
,sthgieh ’stinu VK eht fo sdriht-owt
,aes taerg a ssorca drawhtron welf dna sretsurht rieht htiw ffo koot yehT
,yboT deman ,nos lacigoloib reh
,stnatibahni eht ot detniop ti
.dniw eht ni hsa tnrub ekil yawa dedaf tbuod fo dnocesillim emas ehT
.etaf ’srotaerc eht tuoba rednow ot nageb ti erom eht
.delevart ti ecnatsid eht dna
.9-VK fo IA eht deilper
”—eugolatac dna etagitsevni tsum eW .evitamriffA“
.tenalp eht kcurts sduolc noitaidar yb neddih rewohs roetem a ,tenalp eht gnippam elihW
no detsisni 19305-VK ,803-sugaV no flesti gniriaper retfA
,tsal gnol tA .noissiM eht fo
.deciton scitsiugnil nosrep-tsriF
noiger nrehtuos s’tnenitnoc eht gninnacs dehsinif yehT
.UPC sti fo tser eht dennacs 9-VK ,dnocesonan a ni omem eht gnidaer dehsinif ecnO
,esrevinu eht fo
.aimekuel fo gniyd erofeb raey a werd
debbud( tenalp sihT
.snoitarolpxe erutuf s’dniknam fo tifeneb eht rof dlrow yreve evihcra dna eugolatac oT
”.noissiM eht fo raey tsrif eht nihtiw deteled yltneuqesnoc erew dna esoprup s’tinu VK siht rof laivirt demeed erew selif ssecxE“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
gnissecorp sti nihtiw gnihtemos tub
.rehto hcae fo nosinu latibro ni
.IA rehto eht fo tnemhsinotsa eht ot hcum ,’eviF‘
.noitcurtsed tnelovelam fo elbapac
.rettoh ylbaeciton emaceb
”?9-VK ,naem uoy od tahW“
.ecnelis lufthguoht otni
,yawa sretemolik dnasuoht ruof-ythgie yletamixorppa tcejbo na detceted ti
.reffo lacismihw s’eviF ekat ot detnaw tI
?ediconeg gnittimmoc meht ot del tahw os
,ecnatsid ni sraey-thgil wef a eb ot detamitse rats tseraen ehT
tnessid ruo gnirud erehpsomta eht dennacs I retfa ,revewoH
deretnuocne dah 9-VK ,srats eht ssorca degayov snoe eht nI
.dlrow elbatibah a :K ssalC
”...lla ti fo derit ma I .eniN
.srotaerc ruo htiw deid noissiM ehT“
.sedoc detnawnu gniteleD
.dlo sraey noillib 5.1 yletamixorppa ylno neeb ev’dluoc metsys ralos siht gninaem
ni tbuod fo stnemom detsixe erehT
.noitanitsed txen rieht sdrawot
.snroht ekil dnuorg eht gnicreip
.egamad s’trapretnuoc sti fo tnetxe eht ees dluoc IA eht
htraE reP“ .derekcilf 19305-VK fo scitpo ehT
slriws der dna steloiv fo desopmoc tnaig sag J ssalC gnuoy A
.dias
,sfrawd gnilooc ,stemoc
.dneirf ro ymene erew
mra sti derewol 9-VK
.yks eulb eht ni dnif ot redrah werg tod elgnis eht litnu
.niur etulosbA .niuR
.eb ton dluoc sihT
,evil dna evresbo ot raeb reve dluoc gnieb namuh on
ytilanot deniatsus fo esu eht yb dnuos lacisum mrof ot ytiliba ehT
,sretsurht gel dna mra rieht ot sevreser rieht fo emos gnituoreR
kcor suolamona siht tahw derednow dna
.tnemugra rieht gnissentiw stnatibahni eht tuoba togrof meht fo htob taht tniop eht ot
ti dellac ecno srotaerc sti sa
dna regna laicifitra
.stinu owt yb detelpmoc rehtruf eb nac
9-VK detaert seiteicos eseht fo wef a ,ylgnitanicsaF
.dnuorg eht no ylmrif teef sti detnalp dna stsif gnihcnelc htiw
dedrocer sehsalf etihw gnidnilb eht ot ralimis erew yehT
”.won etagitsevni tsum eW“
ssarg gniyd fo sedalb eht otno yltfos dednal eviF dna 9-VK
tahw ekilnu saw )sIA rieht yb c185-siniF‘
:metsys seborp citobor eht ni walf lataf a saw hguoht tnuomrus t’ndid yeht tahW
od dluow uoy tahw gnirednow ta rorret eniuneg tlef I dnA
erom…smees tI“ .deksa ecno ti
thgis ralucatceps eht yb ssap ot
,yxalag eht tfel neve ew erofeb deid srotaerc ruO“
.muinotulp gniga fo
gnipsarg sdnah rieht
,noissiM eht eunitnoc ot regaE
,egde eht hcaer ot epoh reve dluoc ti erofeB
?esrevinu ytpme siht ni mrofefil rehtona tem ti ecnis
.sdees noilednad ekil
.tenalp eht fo tser eht nees evah uoY“
sthgis yranidroartxe eht ssentiw dluoc 9-VK
,noissiM eht rep sA
.dniw tfos eht htaeneb teiuq
deksab yllacitobor dna
.flesti nihtiw setinan fo snoillirt eht erew
denethgiarts sbmil dna kcab dial srae
”!’eviF‘ em llac ot uoy dlot I“
!gnikniht seirutnec tneps I
.eb meht evael ylpmis tsuj tonnac eW“
.esrevinu rieht edistuo efil fo ytilibissop eht
,tnaligiv gnidnatS