”.gnildeen tnatsnoc eht dna
rennid retfa dna ,tae
.gnar llebrood eht nehw yrruh ot nos sih gnillet txet a tuo gnipyt detrats eH
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.snoitpo egareveb suoirav eht tuo dial d’yeht erehw
.pu ekops lraC erofeb tnelis erew
.mih ta kool ot daeh sti detfil erutaerc ehT
.daeha thgiarts derats dna leehw gnireets eht no pirg sih denethgit lraC
yojne esaelP  .oc.drrac.seyethgin
,llib eht toof evah dluoc eh tub ,erus saw eh ,evisnepxe eb ot dnuob saw tI ?uoy dluoc tub
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW ygolohtna eht ni yrots trohs a
.ni dexim wolley fo stnih htiw swap sti ta etihw ot gnidaf kcab sti gnola skcalb dna syarg krad htiw
.yekrut emos dah tsael ta evah dluoc eW“
”…demaercs ehs yaw eht“ ,dias eh
.noisiced pans a edam dna stsif sih dellab nikraM moT
”floW troppuS lanoitomE“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
,moT deksa ”…eht htiw s’tahW“
.ffuh tfos a edam flow eht dna ,srae eht dniheb dehctarcs dna revo dehcaer eH
,og ot saw nalp eht thguoht I .llah ecnartne
,ffins gib a koot dna adI tnuA ot revo deklaw god ehT
.gnitser ylteiuq saw dna
.tnap desuma na ni tuo dellor eugnot knip gnol ehT
.deggurhs flowerew ehT
,adI tnuA ta kool ot daeh sti detlit
”?yenoh ,rood eht teg uoy naC“
”?flow a evah eh seod yhw ,moT“
.gnivigsknahT deniur uoy woh tuoba gnimaercs eht lla draeh uoY .desivorpmi I“
#  ”!god yegnam taht htiw esuoh siht gnitcepsersid uoy evah won lliw I
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
”.sraey rof em tsniaga siht dloh ot gniog er’yehT“
.seohs evisnepxe ylrevo reh no thgir eep ot gel sti detfil neht dna
,ytilautcnup no msicitirc detniop reh fo emos lraC evig ot ydaer saw dna hcuoc eht morf pu nettog dah ehS .adI deksa
.rekamelbuort nwonk a ,gnirpsyaD seyethgiN yb
.reyof eht ot revo gniklaw ,moT deilper ”,eruS“
gninialpmoc sih ”—ydaerla si adI“
,lraC ,dlihc tsegnuoy s’nikraM eht
.teews etiuq yllaer s’eh tub ,hcuot a evah thgim eh dias retlehs eht ta elpoep ehT“
”.si ti nekcihc egnarO“
”!tsoc eseht hcum woh wonk uoy od ,seohs yM“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.evruc elkcis a ni dleh dna
kroY weN ot kcab evird eht fo setunim net tsrif ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,syadiloH yppaH
lluf saw liat ehT
.lraC morf nettog d’eh txet tsal eht ta kool ot ppa regnessem sih ot revo depiws eH
.etaruccani neeb evah dluow god a ti llac oT
.esuoh eht fo moor gnivil eht otni deklaw ehs erofeb dias adI
,yawecnartne eht nI  .htob ylbaborP
eht fo elddim eht ni thgir og tel uoy tub ,haeY“
.rood eht rof dehcaer dna trihs sih denethgiarts eh
.elbat eht tes ot erawrevlis dna setalp eht tuo gnitros morf pu gnikool ,tenaJ dias ”,ti edam eh ,eeS“
.taes regnessap sih ni gnittis nam eht ta kcab dekool dna denrut lraC  ”.dooG“
sknil eht gniwollof yb skrow sih fo erom dna
.snoitome ruoy llems nac I tegrof uoY“
.rood eht denepo eh sa dias eh ”,oddik ,etal er’uoY“
.gabdnah reh htiw akhsiM tih ot deirt dna ,dah ehs eniw fo ssalg eht deppord
!tnatsni siht esuoh siht fo tuo erutaerc taht dna flesruoy ekaT“
.sdik gnuoy owt rieht sulp ,ysseB efiw sih htiw nhoJ
”?yrassecen yllaer taht saW“
00:3 ta gnivirra detrats stseug ehT
”.akhsiM ,adI tnuA ot ih yas oG
.srae tcere dna eson knalb ynihs a htiw
gnirpsyaD seyethgiN yb
”,kroY weN morf evird a etiuq s’tI“
erofeb adI tnuA tuoba em dlot uoy ,sulP
.dias ti ,etal gninnur yrroS
elzzum derepat a dah tI
”?thgir ,flow a ton s’ti“
”?gnivigsknahT no pirt dnuor ruoh-xis a rof rebU na teg nac uoY“  .adI dias
,demaercs adI tnuA
,gnihtyna yas t’ndid lraC
”,did uoy fi gnivigsknahT rof ereh lla meht dah evah dluoc uoy—
”?nekcihc egnaro tnaw uoY“
.ecnediser nikraM eht ta 03:4 ta rennid rof
,taht tuoba thguoht t’ndah eH .moT deksa
dna dnabsuh reh htiw araS
,esruoc eht rof rap teY
.ta dekool ti ohw enoyna otni erob ot demees taht seye wolley gnicreip dah lamina ehT
”,dlihc lautcnup a saw reven eH“  .etal saw
,gnirpsyaD seyethgiN yb
.liat sih deggaw ahcsiM
.taorht reh deraelc tenaJ
,skooB lakcaJ gnicnaD ta ,recnaD nedloG eht fo sracS ,levon tsetal sih dnif nac uoY
”,ynnuf ytterp saw tahT“
.seyethgin ta
.rac sih fo taes regnessap eht ni gnittis flow eht deksa eh
.rekihhctih flowerew
”floW troppuS lanoitomE“ saw sihT
.nevo eht fo tuo emoc ot ydaer dna erutarepmet ot pu tsomla saw ti dias retemomreht sseleriw eht rof ppa ehT .yekrut eht kcehc ot enohp sih tuo dellup dna dehgis moT
.moor gnivil eht otni delf ehs ,eep fo tnerrot eht pots t’ndid taht nehW
.syadiloh eht rof won kooh eht ffo er’uoY
pu delruc dah tI
,rennid gnivigsknahT fo noitapicitna ni evila tlef esuoh ehT
”floW troppuS lanoitomE“
.lraC ot txen eninac egral eht drawot gnirutseg
”,nac uoy erus m’I“
kst ksT“  ”.emit no ereh saw eh os tsuj taht od ot enoemos ksa t’ndluow I“
,yggahs dna kciht saw ruf ehT
.nos sih ot dias eh
”?yawyna yadot od ot evah ylimaf on htiw nosrep elgnis a seod esle tahW“ .adI dias
emag eht gnihctaw araS dna nhoJ tuoba saw taht saw ti fi erus t’nsaw moT dna ,moor gnivil eht ni daeh reh gnikahs saw adI
.reh ot txen deppets
”.lamina troppus lanoitome ym s’tI“
.tnerap ot emit saw tI
”.ylrae desucxe em steg taht gnihtemos od ot
.ereht thgir s’ti ,noitartsurf taht lla ,noisserped taht llA
.ssecorp llits ot gniyrt ,gninrut moT dias ”,flow a ton s’tI“
.redrah neve deggaw liat ehT
.kcab teg ew nehw nepo eb llits lliw ekil uoy ecalp esenihC taht ,won gnivael yb ,yawynA
flow a niaga saw ereht ,kcab dekool eh nehw dna
.adI tnuA ta denworf ,tenaJ ,efiw s’moT
.lraC dias ”,dad ,iH“
.emit no eb dluow lraC tnaem ti fi
nehctik eht ni draobedis eht ta eniw fo ssalg a flesreh gniruop saw ehs sa adI tnuA dekramer
.etal gnieb lraC tuoba ro
.doog leef moT edam taht dna
.taes regnessap sih ni pu delruc
.sdnuop derdnuh a revo ylisae saw tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,emit no ereht erew sdik tsedlo owt siH
.lraC was eh nehw deid
.draug ffo reh thguac dah siht tpecxe
”,raed ,rebu na tnes evah dluohs uoY“  .dias ehs
”?klat ot tnaw uoy won ,hO“
.daor eht ta kcab kool ot denrut dna foow evissimsid a edam akhsiM  ”.yekrut
.oga sruoh owt revo saw tahT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro