.rae eno fo pit eht ot kcil tfos A
.ksa ot evah t’ndid I
.emit dnoces a rof emit tsrif ehT
,nelots saw htaerB
,maerd a tsuj saw ti fi nevE
.smra sih ni saw I neht dna
.srevol gnuoy fo ssendrawkwa eht ro selcsum deniarts fo niap eht fo enon dleh tnemom eht tuB
.dessim d’ew selims eht lla mih rof delims I
.luos eht fo noitcafsitas eht hguorht delgnit hself eht fo erusaelP
.mih rof decar ti sa taeb rehtona deppiks traeh ym ,edisnI
?ti edisgnola kcil eh did
,enim revo wap sih decalp eH
.snoitseuq erom on erew erehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,em ot flesmih dedluom eH
.noom eht ot ezag sih denrut eH
.decalper neeb reven dah taht
,naidireM aroaF yb ”ytpmE“ saw sihT
.retne mih was reven I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,eye ym fo renroc eht ni ereht thgir
.gnimoc saw tahw wenk eH
.maerd a tsuj lla saw tI
.deb sih ni llits
.keehc sih puc ot nwo ym fo elims a htiw pu dehcaer I
.dekaep ew sa dessik eW
.gnol os rof ytpme neeb dah
spih sih htiw dellor emiT
.enim tsniaga pu desserp ydob siH
.ruf ym hguorht sekorts eltneG
.su dnuora nrut dlrow eht tlef I thguoht I
traeh ym sa tsuj
taht ot liat ym fo pit eht morf gnihtyrevE
”ytpmE“   :yojne esaelP
.worbeye dekrep ylgumS
.liat ym htaeneb sserp
.ecaf ym ssorca nettirw ti ees ot devol d’eH
.ereht saw eH .ereht saw eH
.tsal ta dlrow eht htiw thgir saw lla dna ,niaga og tel ot evah reve
.ti devol d’eh wenk I
,mih rof dessim d’I selims eht lla
,ruf ym hguorht nar eH
,keehc ym dekorts swap sih fo enO .ti tlef htob eW
,llits em dedule ssenlufekaw lluF
sesiurb dna sracs dna stuc ssorca decart eH
,emoclew saw diov taht llif ot lla ta gnihtynA
.derotser ertsul tsol a
,esolc ni denael eh sa elims ykeehc taht ees llits dluoc I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.oga sedaceD .oga sraey
,detnaw dah ew semit eht noitom otni tes maerd ehT
.maerd a tsuj lla saw tI
.hcuot sih yb denokceb
.ekaw rieht ni ygrene gnimmuh
.sih no dekcol ,seye yM
.ecneserp sih noitseuq t’ndid I
.seiromem tseilrae ehT
.tuo yad dna ni yad
,mih htiw em detfil eh sa
.kaeps ot evah t’ndid I
.erus saw I ebyaM
.efil wen nevig ylneddus
I dna repeed deirrac taeh ehT
.hcuot sih rednu dewener flesym tlef I
ygrene wen sti htiw gnis ydob ym tlef I
.sgninrom retniw looc dna sthgin remmus toh eht llA
taht htmraw a deirrac hcuot sih tuB
.denruter ygrene ym sa neve
.thgilnoom eht otni kcab
derettam taht llA
.nelots neeb dah luos dna
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.delims I ,daetsnI
.ytirutam fo erised nevird dna ecneirepxe eht htiw htuoy fo seidob eht dleh maerd ehT
taht tfel yeht dellevart sregnif sih reverehw dna
yromem morf neve tsol gnol ,snoitoM
.emit a trohs revewoh rof
.ot desu eh ekil tsuj
.ecneserp sih htiw tsuj demmuh
sa wollip a ta dehcnelc sregniF .delbmert
.elims yhtoot ,degguR
hguorht 8# GNAF ni dehsilbup tsrif yrots siht dah ohw
.wap sih em dereffo ;em ot deddon eH
derettam taht llA
.tif taht eceip gnissim eht saw eH
rae dekcil yltfos
– luos ym ,traeh ym – ydob yM
mraw elims sih was I sa dna
– nwo ym ssorca debbur elzzum siH
.elims yppah yletarepsed a
.ecaf enipul ralugnA
?diarfa neeb evah I dluohS
.seigolohtna yrruf erom lareves ni sa llew sa
.tem d’ew nehw neeb dah ti ekil peed dna
.emit tsrif eht dah I sa tsuj
?wolg revlis s’noom lluf eht ni dehtaehs
.ecipicerp eht ta decarb I
.niaga ehtaerb yllanif dluoc I hguoht sa tlef I ,ekorb ew nehW
denoitseuq t’ndah I sa tsuj
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ereht saw eh ,ton ro maerD
.tfahs sih gnola nwod dna pu edor I sa
.em edisni deppils eh sa noitapicitna nekorb fo elbmert taht
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.egde yrev eht ta ereht regnil
eceip eht saw eH
.gnol os ,os ni decneirepxe d’I gnihton ekil dellif ssenitpme ym fo erom tlef I
ytsur ,denruter der eht dna dedaf yerg ehT
.sgnirps thgirb dna snmutua yretsulb eht llA
.em dehctaw eh sa thgilnoom eht ni deremmihs seye siH
.evael su ees ot ereht saw eno oN
em neewteb dils smra sih fo eno sa ruogiv dewener htiw depmup tI
.yhw ro woh rettam t’ndid tI
,hself eht htaeneb ,ruf eht htaeneb knas
.enim ot dehcuot daeherof sih nehw dehsinav ylno ti dna
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.evah tey d’ew selims eht lla mih rof delims I
.erus eb ot detnaw I ebyaM
,thgit em dezeeuqs eh sa tsehc ym deppirg ssenthgiT
.ylsseltroffe os ni dils d’eh woh
,yawa debbe hself eht fo egrus ehT
htiw ti dleh I .raen mih tlef d’I emit tsal eht ti dleh d’I pirg emas eht htiw ,ylthgit ti depsarg I
.thgil sti rednu em tnuh emoc ot flow a ekil woH
.dnatsrednu ot evah neve t’ndid I
,reve sa erus sa ,mih tlef I nehw
.oga gnol os tlep der-tessur
.dellifluf deniamer ssenitpme eht tub
noitirappa siht yb ylsuorogiv os nekat eb ot ygrene eht dnuof I erehw erac t’ndid I
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  naidireM aroaF yb
.og tel ot tuoba t’nsaw I
?ot tnaw I dluow yhw dna ,evom t’ndluoc I
,tenalpruF
.trofmocsid ro niap fo kcal eht tuoba kniht t’ndid I .gnol oot
,naidireM aroaF yb ”ytpmE“
.ydob ym revo lla devom swap siH .devom eh dnA
.tsap enog gnol semit fo rednimer a ekil
em ta dekniw eh dna
.og tel – t’ndluoc ohw – t’ndluow
,ylhtooms os wardhtiw mih tlef I woh noitseuq t’ndid I
.em dniheb htmraw tnatsnoc a deniamer ecneserp sih tub ,sisylarap ym detfil maerd ehT
.dehcaorppa dne eht sa mih htiw detnap I
.peed mih decrof dna
.noissap fo seorht eht ni rehtegot dekcol seidob fo elbmert a ;riaffa tnelis A
.ereht saw ohw wenk I
.ssel tnaw dluoc I dlrow eht ni gnihton saw erehT
.rae tfel nrot ,yttaR
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.kcen ym fo kcab eht no htaerb toh ehT
tfird ot mees tsomla mih dehctaw I sa yppup elttil a ekil
delims I .sraey ni gnilims rebmemer dluoc I elims tsegral eht saw ti dna ,kcab delims I
.mih ees llits dluoc I dnA
,neht dna ti dewollof I
.ylecreif ti dehctulc I dna ,elddim ym dnuora parw ot detfil mra nA
,xof dlo ytpme eht ssorca tfird ot deunitnoc thgilnoom ehT
,ti ssorca delwarc thgilnoom eht sa enohs ruf-wap kcalB
;hctiwt tahT
.tem tsrif dah ew nehw dah ti yaw emas eht ecar traeh dlo ym tlef eh fi derednow I
.niaga mih ees dluoc I dna
.flesym detrexe I hcihw htiw esae eht noitseuq t’ndid I
dna emit yb derepmet ,seiromem lla saw tI
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.dootsrednu eh wenk I
.em dniheb hturt eht dootsrednu I .was I
won yromem a tub saw hcaE
.emit tsrif eht dah eh sa tsuj em ta delims eH
dekrep srae ,pu tas ylpmis I
.saw syawla eh lived yoc eht ekil
,em hguorht erob ot demees seye siH
.mih nopu dehcnelc I sa doohelam sih deppirg ssenthgit dna
,ereht ti ees eh dluoC
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.eye ym thguac eh sa kcab delims eH
.gnol oot ni neeb t’ndah ti yaw a ni thgir saw gnihtyrevE
mih pota demriuqs I dna
.did I os dna ,evom dluoc I
.evol tsol gnol a fo
.ot erapmoc t’ndluoc ytilaer taht enihs tcefrep a ot dehsilop
.waj ym gnola dna keehc ym nwod yltnesba decart sregnif siH
.mih dnuora dna tsniaga dna rof koohs I elihw em ta nwod elims ot mih ekil woH
.pu ekaw t’ndluoc I taht rettam t’ndid tI .dah I taht dna
?dekcohS ?niatrecnu
,seye ym nepo t’ndluoc I
neeb ecno dah tahw hguorht sregnif derruf-kcalb
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.flah a dna ega na rof tlefnu tnaw a htiw
.sih dnuora depparw ydob ym
ni emit tsrif eht rof nepo em daerps ti sa doohelam sih noitseuq t’ndid I
.ylisae os flesym otni mih koot I yhw
dah I sa ylerus sa tsuj ,lla meht tlef I
.esoht fo enon saw I
,kcab ym no em denrut eH
.htaeneb sserttam dlo yttar eht dna
.erom ecno tem selzzum ruo sa
.ydob ym fo llaf dna esir yreve htiw rehtegot dedlem yehT
.pael dna nur dna gnis dna evom dluoc I hguoht sa tlef I
.erofeb kcab yaw …nehw kcab yaW
neeb evah I dluohS
.enim yb dewodahs ydob sih htiw pal sih ni dna smra sih nI
;em dnuora smra sih fo leef eht derebmemer I
,ytiniffAruF dna yrruFoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,kcab ylneddus dehsur
rettam t’ndid tI
dehca taht selcsum dekrow
,kcab denael eh sa ti ffo dna pu em detfil eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.yhw wenk neve I ebyaM
,reven dluow I taht neht wenk I
– ot ekil did syawla eH
dna esuap ot ylno ,deb eht morf ylsselmaes deppils eh sa tnew eh rehtruF
.kcab ym ta htmraw sih leef dluoc I
.taorht ym ni thguac htaerB
dna erats nekorbnu nA
.emoh saw eH .ereh saw eH
.thgin eht fo elddim eht ni devirra eh sa ,esruoc fo ,mih tlef I
.sih deppuc I woh ot rorrim a
,dellif deniamer tI
.tnemom a rof etatiseh t’ndid I
.tsehc ym no rehto sih
.mih erofeb dnem meht tlef I dna
,dlihc a saw I ecnis tlef ton d’I yaw a ni eerf tlef I
mih tsniaga nwod erob I
.nwod erob I sa mih htiw dellews I
enob dna elcsum dna wenis derit eht hguorht
ohw eno fo pirg eht
dehtaehsnu swalc
.hcuot sih rednu delgnit gnihtyrevE
.meht deen t’ndid I tub
– ?owt ti saw ro – taeb a piks ti tlef eh fi derednow I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.nwo ym no dekcol ,seye sih erew
.woleb deb eht ot dna tsac I wodahs eht tsap
.kcab erob I .demriuqs I .devom I ,hO
.em morf kcab llup ot nageb eH
.evol yb detum ,evoL
.maerd tseb ehT
.em otni pu edils depleh eh sa
,ereht saw eh taht saw
sraey ni os detfihs t’ndah taht senob dlO