,deddon ireC ”?naem uoY“
.noziroh eht ot resolc seerged evif depmuj dah nus eht
.stnedicca on droffa dluoc ehS
,elpmet eht fo roiretni eht til dah taht sehcrot eiree eht fo reh dednimer
,emit gnol a rof tnelis saw ireC
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,ecnelis ni doots ilyeT ,gnidnuop traeH
,niaga reh ot derepsihw elpmet ehT
.esolc ireC dellup dna delims ilyeT
.hcuot eht ot looc yllarutannu tlef llits ehs tub
.thgir eht no esacriats eht debmilc ilyeT sa esnopser on edam elpmet ehT
,snrecnoc s’ilyeT rof tcepser fo tuo ,ylniatrec
reh ot ekops elpmet ehT
hcnul rof deppots yeht emit eht yb gnirevihs htob erew yehT
”,ezilaer t’ndid I“
seye reh ,depsag nooccar ehT
.renroc hcae ni hcrot a yb ylluf til dna
,esroh a ekil erugif a gnilaever
.seye s’ireC htiw
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,enrohtwaH .S.J yb
!segaugnal tneicna eht yduts ton tsdid uoht taht gniod ruo ton si tI“
.nepo gnitoohs
.erutuf eht tuoba klat ilyeT ot denetsil ehs nehw ,did syawla ti sa ,gninetfos noisserpxe reh ,delims ireC
.cigam fo elcric eht yb dednuober dna
.seolf niht-repap naht erom gnimrof morf eci tneverp ot hguone tsuj retaw eht detaeh lamreht dnuorgrednu emos
,erif toh gniraor a gnidliub dna
”.ysae si eciohc ym nehT“ ”.oN“
.slatsedep eht fo eno fo pot eht ot pu gnihcaer eno hcae
,sniatnuom owt fo esab eht ta tas sniur elpmet ehT
.ydob reh fo htmraw eht leef ot hguone esolc
.ylppus trohs ylgnissertsid ni htob erew cigam dna efil s’ireC taht thguoht ilyeT ,yletavirP ”.dezilaer dah I fi erofeb ti xif ot gnihtemos enod evah dluow I
.tsehc s’ireC tsniaga remmuS fo waL eht desserp ilyeT
.sdrow dednecsnart taht evol a dna
.reh fo tnorf ni ydaets dleh drows
.noitnetta elttil meht diap hcihw ,tsaeb kcap eht dnoyeb meht ees ot dnuora saw eno on hguoht
.wons yb deteknalb dlrow a fo ecnelis eht tub
,tsaeb kcap eht fo retlehs eht ni reh htiw deldduh dna
.revihs ot neve dloc oot
.reh edisni dlihc eht fo eglub eht no ylbatrofmoc gnitser
rebmuls taht sgniht dlo eht
erofeb thgin eht tsac dah ehs slleps eht dekcehc ireC
.srood enots evissam fo tes a saw sriats eht morf dne raf eht tA
.dedne dah ssik rieht nehw
.stneicna fo eciov eht ma I“
”?pu tiaw uoy dluoW“
”.gnorw eb llits thgim I“
,yawa llef dnas eht elihw deraor taht wam gnipag a otni gninepo
”,traeh ym ,tnaw uoy tahw s’ti fI“
”,tneconni na si dlihc ehT“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.esoht derongi ilyeT tub
.ruf reh no dniw remmus teews ekil htaerb sti tlef ehS
.deksa ilyeT ”?od I od tahW“
,yawllah niam eht ffo tsuj tas
.htworg wen fo stoohs wef tsrif eht htiw decalper
,delbmur elpmet eritne eht
,hcamots reh fo eglub eht tsniaga dnah a desserp ilyeT
”.htap siht esoohc uoht fi dlrow yht evas ot elba eb ton tliw uohT“
.dnaletsaw ywons eht hguorht deohce eciov s’erah ehT
,deklaw ehs gnol woh wonk ton did ehS
.esnopser on saw ereht tuB ”.uoy knahT“
.sehcrot esoht ot meop eht fo tser eht tcennoc ot gniyrt setunim sseltiurf lareves tneps ehs dna
taruggiz gniddibrof a dna stnemele fo seirutnec derehtaew ylroop dah taht draytruoc elkcahsmar a
.ti dnuora dnah reh desolc ehs sa gniteelf dna naw demees thgilnus sti dna
?ylsuoenatlumis efiw ym dna dlrow ym evas I naC“
”!pu tiaw ,ireC“  enrohtwaH .S.J yb
”.emyhr neve t’nseod tI“
,semaG eniugnaS yb ygolohtna walcnorI na
.ecnartne s’elpmet eht fo sedirts eerht nihtiw
.sreksihw reh tsap deltsihw ti sa edalb yreif eht fo taeh eht gnileef
,nwod detlem roolf eht fo noitces ralucric a ,esnopser nI
staes desiar htiw dellif
,aet eht fo erom knird ot yrT“
,tsrif demrof htuom A
.htaeneb worg ot deganam dah taht ssarg rednet yna rof gnigarof
,esor dna elkcusyenoh fo gnillems
.droc rehtael elpmis a htiw
,gnihtyna yas t’ndluow ehS
.thgin eht ni esolc sserp ot nooccar reh desuac taht llihc a naht ereves erom erew stceffe-edis eht sselnu ton
.hsurc drayloohcs a saw ti
.latrom O ,gniksa eht rof ton si ezirp a hcuS“
.pu gnikool dna egdir eht fo mottob eht ta gnippots
,srood eht tsniaga efil ot dezalb gnitirw tneicnA
.eye thgir s’ireC ni gnirekcilf dna mid
,htaerb rof gnitnap saw ilyeT litnu
.naidisbo kcalb gniwolg erew seye s’esroh ehT
.redwop fo hcni raelc a ni derevoc ydaerla saw
smoor lainomerec eguH
.rehtegot dexim lla
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb ygolohtna rorroh a ,egatooF dnuoF
,ilyeT dednamed ”?drow
ssom daed fo dellems dna
,trapa ekorb yllanif yeht nehW
.ereht pu worg ton llahs tub
,regnil ti tel dna ssik a htiw reh deppots ilyeT tub ,erom yas ot detrats ehS ”.yrros m’I“
.rehtom dloc ,thgil ni nwarD“
.daeh reh koohs neht ,detatiseh ireC
”!latrom O ,ecneitap ruo ton tseT“
,drah fo sraey owt
.wollof dluow erom
.taorht reh ni thguac htaerb s’ilyeT
.knab wons a otni tsrif-ecaf delwarps dna ,pets reh dessim
.esacriats eht otni nwod deralg ilyeT
,siri thgir reh dednuorrus dah thgil egnaro fo gnir tnaillirb a
,dna derruf-krad saw ireC erehW
.mlaer eht ssorca ecracs gnitteg saw doof dna ,gniworg sporc tpek cigam ylnO
,seye nworb peed dah dah ireC
dias ehs ”,diarfa m’I ,etiuq toN“
.ydob tcefrep eht noinipo
.ti htaeneb
.redluohs s’ilyeT otni derumrum ehs ”,kcolb a s’ereht ekil s’tI“
”retniW sseldnE“   :yojne esaelP
.yltnacifingis pu demraw dah tub
,stfird wons peed eht hguorht edaw ot delggurts ehS
.yek elohw eht eb thgim ti
elats saw edisni ria ehT
saw ria eht ,sriats eht fo dne eht dehcaer ehs nehw tub
.tnenoppo latrom a gnurtsmah evah dluow taht ekirts a
.tnelis ylnrobbuts deniamer elpmet ehT .deksa ilyeT
,elkcuhc yrw a htiW
”.ecnalab ot dlrow siht erotser dna
.latrom O ,eeht ot pu si tahT“ ”?deeccus ew lliW“
.evael ot ecnatculer reh no emit s’ireC fo erom yna gnidneps ecnahc ot gnilliw ton
,ybab eht ot gniwo
.ecafrus eht dehcaer ilyeT nehw
gnol os rof teiuq saw ireC
,ffats reh no gninael
doots yeht hcihw ta egdir eht fo pot ehT .deksa ilyeT ”?ti si rehtraf hcum woH“
tip eht no nwod gnimmals sevooh evissam sti
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.dehctaw gnieb fo gnileef gnipeerc eht dna
.uoy morf raeh ot evol d’I dna
.elpmet eht edisni elbaliava saw thgil dna efil elttil tahw ot gnilc ot deganam dah taht
remmuS fo waL ehT—latsyrc ehT
,elcric eht otni kcab deppets ireC
.dewollaws ilyeT
,elbmur ekauqhtrae na htiw denepo reh dniheb srood eht nehw demaercs ehS
.daeh reh koohs ireC
naidraug eht ot nosirapmoc ni lufitip dna llams os—drows nwo reh gnignirb
,drawrof edorts ehs erofeb tekcop reh otni kcab ti dils dna
,daeh sti revo nwod ti thguorb neht dna
.wonk t’ndid I ,ilyeT ,cigam dna efil ym no
.elpmet eht ot tuo dellac ehs ”,egaugnal taht kaeps t’nod I“
,dednopser ireC ”,ytipidneres tsuj ,oN“
s’erah eht ni—ilyeT naht reivaeh elttil a tub ehtil saw ehS
,detaerc dah ireC taht gnir detnahcne eht ni yltfiws detlem tI
.hcamots reh no gnitser dnah eno
,ireC ot resolc pets a koot ehS
,wons tneserpinmo eht tsniaga tuo doots
,emit emos rof ecnelis ni deklaw yehT
,ymedacA eht morf detaudarg dah ehs ecnis tub
.erow ehs ,tsaeb nrehtron-raf emos fo edih etihw yelacs eht morf edam
llordeb detliuq rieht tuo dial ilyeT elihW
,mra eht ni reh thguac ekirts driht ehT
”.em morf gniward neeb ev’I os
,elbisivni ylraen saw ilyeT
.hcamots s’esroh eht otni pu edalb reh fo edis eht gnignirb
neht dna dnah dereffo eht koot ireC
,psarg s’ilyeT ni mraw niaga ecno ,ydob reh
.sgninrom eht ni deklat reven yehT
,erofeb tnemom a naht ssel neeb dah toof s’ilyeT erehw dnuorg eht kcurts dna llef exa ehT
.yltniaf gnilims ,dias ilyeT ”,enif s’eH“
,gninrom lla ffo dna no deirrulf wonS
,3nrohtwahsj@ ,rettiwT reh tuo kcehC
drows reh werd ilyeT
.yllanif dias ehs ”,yrros m’I“
.spets wef tsal eht ilyeT pleh ot dnah a tuo gnihcaer
”,eno elttil ,em dna uoy tsuJ“
stoob dna kaolc reh ffo dellup ireC nehW .eb deen fi
.woleb egats ydnas eht dehcaer dah ehs ecno
.thgis morf gnihsinav
.erif fo demrof edalb a htiw ilyeT sa gib sa exa na dleh tI
.og tnemugra eht tel ton dluoc ehs ,llits tuB
,elims deifsitas a htiW
.ria eht ta gnilffuns
,remmus ro gnirps on htiw raey a tuoba denialpmoc dna dekwauqs dna deprihc sdriB
,ilyeT ,ti leef nac I“
.pu drows reh gnidloh llits
.wons ni peed elkna
,pu yawflah saw erah eht emit eht yB
.noitisop gnittis a otni ireC gnipleh dna hsuls dna eci eht ni gnileenk
,ylgnigilbo nwod dial tI
pu exa eht tpews esroh-dnas ehT
.flah ni reh tilps ot deraperp
dloc eht otni kcab dna
.sevlesmeht senots eht hguorht etanoser ot demees tI
,meht denepo ehs nehW
”!noom eht si rewsna ehT“
.meht erofeb elzzup eht fo eceip a evah thgim taht
”!gnihtyreve evas oT“
.revo tsaeb kcap eht thguorb ehs
.doolb fo enil kciht a gniward
,nwo sti no gniog saw erif eht ecnO
,ekal eht morf eci fo kcarc tfos eht ro
retaehtihpma eht ekahs ot hguone duol delworg dna delbmuts esroh ehT
.tlahs uoht eveileb ew ,sey tuB
.semalf eht fo suidar gnimraw eht nihtiw ireC gnignirb
eeht ksa lliw eW“
,mra reh htiw ecaf reh derevoc ehS
,ffats reh no ylivaeh denael nooccar ehT
”.eeht pots ton lliw ew
”.dloc ssel elttil a retniw eht edam eW
leef t’ndid ireC taht flesreh dlot ehS
.reh thguat dah sdneirf rehto fo lufdnah a dna ireC tahw ot detimil saw tfarcegam fo egdelwonk reh dna
,dnah reh ni llits drows reh ,ilyeT
.sniatnuom dnalhgih eht gnidnuorrus sllihtoof hguor eht otni gnidaeh
.taht erofeb gninrom yreve dna
.eldnac a ekil rekcilf ot retaw-noom eht fo thgil eht desuac ti fo ecrof eht dna
”.niaga sevil dna sedaf ,sworG
,eci dna wons ni dnal eht teknalb ot nugeb dah retniW sseldnE eht erofeb sraey ,tem tsrif dah yeht nehW
”retniW sseldnE“ saw sihT
.dloc saw ehs kniht t’ndid ehs tub
.denihs ylraen yeht litnu dehsurb erew riah dna ruf
,deohce llac eht sa dehctiwt rae reH
.taorht reh ni thguac eciov reh tub
”?waL eht kees uoht tsod eroferehW“
meht ot rettam ton did taht tub
.setispmac esoht lla etaerc uoy tel evah t’ndluohs I“ .deddon ireC
,ireC ot detfird sthguoht reH
.resolc elttil a nooccar eht degguh ylevixelfer ohw
.retaw-noom reh fo thgil eht dnoyeb ssenkrad eht otni gnirats
ruoy si doog tahW“ ”.snoitcani ro snoitca ruo hguorht
.ezeeuqs tfos a dnah reh evag dna
,luferac eb ot deirt ehS
thgil tuoba trap ehT
,semalf elprup dna eulb eiree htiw efil ot dezalb sehcrot
ireC no gnikat saw ti llot eht ta deirrow ilyeT .nwot ot nwot morf gnihcterts
.thginrevo owt ro hcni rehtona niag thgim ti hguoht
saw erif fo anoroc eht ees ot demrala saw ilyeT dna ,seye reh denepo ehS
emas eht deniamer eye tfel reH
reh dna ,gnimoorg reh tuoba suoiditsaf saw nooccar ehT
s’ireC htiw sregnif reh deniwtretni ilyeT ”.nrob saw eh litnu egufeR s’dnoceS ni deyats evah dluohs eW“ .dehgis ireC ”?yako ,elttil a nwod wols ot deen tsuj uoY .enif htob er’eW“
,noos thgin eht rof tser nac eW“
,llew sa ,meht ot denruter seciov rieht nooS
,eniwtretni dna worg ot decreoc ,stnalp eht yllautneve dna
thgil eht hsiugnitxe ot retaw-noom fo elttob eht dessik ilyeT .swodahs gnirekcilf htiw retaehtihpma eht gnidoolf
,ecnelis elbatrofmocnu na ton saw tI
gnol sehcni ruof ylerab saw—
swons fo dnal a ni nrob eb lliw dlihc yht :siht wonk
”.dlrow ruo evas oT“
,ilyeT ,erah eht
”.nekorB“ ,derumrum ireC
,drows reh dehtaehs ehs sa rood eht deiduts ilyeT ”.niaga sevil dna sedaf ,sworG
gnimochtrof eht ni dna
drowssap eht kaeps dna siht raeH“
.tserof ywons eht revo dnah eerf reh devaw ehs
,raey tsap eht revo ,dah ehS
,derettum ehs ”,eniF“
,deganam ireC ”,eb tsuM“
htorb dna aet ireC edam ilyeT htiw gnirud ,ruoh na saw tI
.wol denrub sehcrot egnarts eht
.detrap yllanif yeht nehw nooccar eht dlot ilyeT
.yaw rieht gnissap srelevart rehto yna rof retlehs dna doof edivorp dluow dna
seye gniyrp morf meht dedleihs taht egdeh eht gnitaerc tneps dah ehs cigam eht fo tceffe-edis a ,wenk ehs ,saw tI
,dnopser ot denrut ireC
.tnalpgge dna otamot demraw-nus dna
,tsaeb kcap rieht fo snier eht no deggut
reh gnikahs fo egrev eht no tsuj saw ilyeT
,wons eht hguorht gnilffuns saw ti ,daetsnI
,emit revo edaf dluow cigam ehT
”?noitpo rehtona ereht sI“
,stun dna seirreb fo tsaef a htiw erifpmac llams a dnuora delttes yeht ,dne eht nI
dellac ehs ”?tahw woN“
,reh ta nwod gnirewolg
,detuohs ilyeT ”!ybab yM“
,ylsseldrow ,wonk ireC tel did ehS
,yadhtrib tsrif sih yB
.ecaf reh no gnillaf wons ot ekow
taht dias ,revewoh ,ton dah ehS
”.su eb ot evah t’nseod tI
.dlrow eht ot denruter dnuos
.raf os og ylno dluoc krab dna seirrebpsar taht dezingocer ehs neve tub
,nwod detaolf wonS
.skaolc rieht yb debircsmucric saw dlrow eht lla noos dna
,kaerb on htiw htrae eht otni peed delarips yehT
.tuo dnah reh gnidloh
.tsehc reh dehcuot dnah reH
.ti ot evol eurt eno reh fo eman eht derepsihw dna
egral ton saw sriats eht fo mottob eht ta moor ehT
”.ti pleh nac uoy fi evom ot ton yrt
,wons peed eht hguorht gnigdurT
.drawnwod sriats eht wollof ot nageb ehs tcaer ton did elpmet eht nehW
,sraey ni fo thguoht t’ndah ehs enoemos ,rehtaf reh ekil dednuos tI
”.tluaf ym si sihT“
.rehtegot dekcilc lla ti neht dna
dnuora tsaeb kcap eht thguorb ilyeT
,retnec eht ni doots slatsedep owT
.evol ym ,gniht doog a did uoY .oN“
hcuop reh ta deporg ehS
,llaf ot detrats dah swons eht ecnis sraey owt neeb dah tI
,tub dnuorg eht morf detpure dnaS
,eno siht ekil tsuj segdeh fo ,sderdnuh spahrep ,snezod detaerc
.kcatta reh fo mutnemom eht htiw drawrof dellor ilyeT sa dnas fo rewohs a htiw hguorht dessap tI
.denrut ehs erofeb semit lareves wons eht ta dehsal liat gnol s’ireC
.noitacsufbo dna esucxe refforp dna
,dehsulb htob yehT
.tuo ecrof dluoc ireC taht lla saw ”,mraW“
eb ti t’ndluohs yhw tuB“
,ti tsap dekcud ehs sa eenk s’esroh eht otni dna dnuora drows reh deppihw ehS
,dednamed ehs ”?eno hcihW“
,decnavda erutaerc eht sa dnuorg reh dleh ilyeT .dnas fo snoisolpxe llams ni
”?waL eht kees uoht tsod eroferehW“
,sraey rof evila stnalp eht fo tsegnorts eht peek ot lios eht ni niamer dluow rewop hguone neht neve tub
,uoy ot raews I“ .detsetorp ireC
,erofeb evol ni nellaf dah ilyeT fI
wons fo pmac llams a gniraelc krow ot tnew neht ehS .kcab mraw
”?sllah dewollah ruo ,eseht ni kees uoht tsod tahW
.flesti retaehtihpma eht fo edam
ireC rof rrahc niatnuom taf fo elpuoc a dehsif ilyeT dna ,ekal eht ni dehsiruolf llits efiL
”?elddir eht tuoba snoitseuq uoy ksa I yaM“
.drawnwod yaw eht gnitanimulli
.dednopser elpmet eht
.kniht I ,noonretfa worromot elpmet dlo eht hcaer neht
,tif doog a eb dluow kniht uoy yrots trohs a evah uoy fi dnA
.yab ta swons eht tpek revoc niatnuom eht dna
.klaw rieht no tae ot stnalp nworg-wen eht morf doof dekcip osla dna
.ni saw ehs etats eht ni eucser a tnuom thgim ireC taht epoh dnoyeb demees tI
.dnah reh ni gnikahs dna pu drows
dna htrae fo dellems dna digirf
.ecalp siht ni dia rehtruf yna dnif ton dluow yeht taht
,egdir eht fo pot eht ta detiaw ireC .ezag gninrub
,reh ta delrans ti ,niagA
”.em dlot evah dluohs uoY
”?em eb ot evah t’nseod ti naem uoy hcihw yB“
.yltneloiv gnirevihs saw nooccar ehT
,elpmet dlo na rof gnikool erew yeht taht ilyeT dlot dah ehS
”?htob evas latsyrc rehto eht naC
.smra s’ilyeT otni gnixaler
”.thgilnus fo dnal a sevresed eH“
.ti evlos dluoc esle enoemoS“
”?tfel gnihton evah uoy won dnA“
.egarof ot emit gnitsaw diova ot doow delipkcots rieht fo emos gnicifircas
,ilyeT htiw llordeb eht otni edils ot
.detnorffa ,dias ilyeT ”,meop elbirret a tahW“
.peels ot hcihw rednu yks yrrats dna daorb a nemow htob gnivig
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.nrut ton did ehs tub
.eciov eht draeh ehs nehw
.tip eht ot dnecsed reh gnihctaw lla sedahs suohproma dnasuoht a
.rehtaf reh fo eciov eht ni dias ti
.evila dna efas reh peek ot
.flah ni ilyeT gnittilps ylraen ,nwod gnuws ti
,raor emosion a ni nepo htuom
.flesti tes ot deraperp ti sa seert eht fo spot eht gnihsurb tsuj
.redluohs s’erah eht no gnitser daeh reh
.doots llits ilyeT erehw moor eht otni dna
.wolla dluow noituac sa yltfiws sa devom ehS
,drawrof dehsad ehs sa dnas fo yarps a pu gnidnes
.gnirevihs llits ,kaolc reh ni llab a otni pu delruc nooccar ehT
,gninrom suoiverp eht neeb dah ehs sa mraw sa saw ireC taht
,redluohs reh fo yhs tsuj deppots egdeh ehT
,yhw ro ,gniod saw ehs tahw gnidnatsrednu tuohtiW
.reh fo edisni gniworg dlihc eht fo llews eht leef ot drows reh gnisaeler
hguorht pets ot meht rof hguone gib egdeh eht ni eloh a tuc ilyeT ,drows reh htiW
.gniggalf saw ireC taht dootsrednu ilyeT taht niaga gnivom erew dna doots dah yeht litnu t’nsaw ti ,llitS
.snrecnoc esoht dehgiewtuo meht gnitaerc ni tlef ireC taht edirp eht dna did segdeh eht doog eht tub
”?waL eht kees uoht tsod eroferehW“ ”.ma I“
.dimaryp sselega eht otni dehcni dna
.rehtom dloc ,thgil ni nwarD
.egdir eht fo edis raf eht nwod yaw eht del
,ot desu ti naht erif erom dah eye s’nooccar eht fo wolg eht ylniatrec—
,tnemom a rof detatiseh ehS
,deksa ireC ”?ti did uoY“
,ireC dias ”,raf toN“
ilyeT .peels lufecaep a ot ffo detfird owt eht dna
.anoroc s’ireC sa roloc emas eht thgil egnaro na htiw efil ot dezalb ti ,yltnatsnI
tsah uohT“ ”.noitacovorp tuohtiw em dekcatta uoY“
.ti dnatsrednu ylerab dluoc ilyeT taht yldab os gnirettahc erew hteet reh hguoht
,margelet dna rettiwT no yggodikahk@ m’I
,enrohtwaH .S.J yb ”retniW sseldnE“
.tip dnas ralucric a gnidnuorrus
,ekirts eht htiw nups ehS
epacsdnal dellif-wons eht ssorca gnihsad reh dah
.ytuaeb s’ireC yb kcurts niaga ecno saw ilyeT dna tem seye riehT
.pu tsaeb eht del ilyeT sa
,ffats doowlezah delrang eht tsniaga denael ehS
.ylleb reh no dnah s’ireC dial ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
flesreh lliks lacigam on dah ehS
,erifpmac rieht dnuora elcric ediw a deklaw ireC—htmraw dedda eht fo pot no erahs ot tnasaelp erom hcum—
.nepo yltnelis gniws ot nageb srood eht
,rebmahc eht otni deppets ilyeT
.hcae ssapyb tsum dna snaidraug elpirt eht dekovorp tsah uoht ,swal ruo yB
.cinap ffo gnithgif ,deksa ilyeT ”?tahW“
,wolley mraw-nus dewolg htoB
.drows reh no gnitser niaga ecno dnah
.detuohs ehs ”!noom ehT“
.ireC fo thguoht ilyeT
.em htiw hcuot ni teg esaelp
.efil reh naht erom naem dluow
,dlrow yrtniw siht fo secruoser niht eht rof etepmoc ot trats dluow
.potniatnuom eht morf meht no nwod welb ezeerb llihc a dna
.tesnus retfa yltrohs pmac rieht dehcaer ehS
.dnuof eb nac seirots reh erehw no setadpu rof
.roolf tserof eht tsniaga dekcarc spetstoof rieht dna ,shguob ssorca derepmacs slamina dnaldoow llams
,sesacriats gnivruc owt otni devloser ti
”.ytnelp fo dlrow a ni efas dna
,gninrom yreve did ehs sa ,flesreh dlot ilyeT
,retsnom wen a fo daetsni
”?yadretsey cigam eht fo esuaceB“
evol ni nellaf dah ilyeT
,sgnignoleb rieht pu dekcap ilyeT elihW
ssarg tsohg dna nehcil htiw kcils saw roolf ehT .enots dloc dna
,tnasaelpnu erutxet dna etsat eht dnuof ehS
,latsedep eht otni knus ti sa dehctaw ilyeT .ylsuoenatlumis latsyrc rehto eht ni tuo tnew thgil ehT
.ecnetsisni s’ireC ta
.emoc dah ehs htap eht kcab klaw ot
,wol gnuh noom tnecserc ehT
,llihc retniw lauteprep eht etipseD
.tliub dah ilyeT taht erif llams eht ot txen rehtegot deldduh
”,siht ot nrob mih tnaw t’nod I
.yldwerhs dias ilyeT
kcen reh fo esab eht ta kcab dellup
,guh a otni llef dna dnah s’ilyeT desaeler ehS
.erif elprup-eulb emas taht htiw gninrub
.hsif dna krab wolliw
,deksa elpmet eht
saw ehs sa llat sa eciwt srood roiretni fo tes a dehcaer tsuj dah ehS
yppah dlihc yht eeserof eW
:yrassecennu saw tahT
,elcric reh dehsinif ehs emit eht yB
,egnellahc reh ot rewsna nI
,gninraw lanoitidda yna tuohtiW
,rrahc eht fo emos eta neve ilyeT
,redloc riah a tsuj
,derevihs regnol on ehS
.ekal eht ssorca ffats reh fo pit eht htiw gnitniop
.retniw gnidleiynu
,kaolc eht ni neve
.eciov eht fo ecruos eht etacol ot tpmetta ot ecalp ni gninnips
”,nac I sa noos sa kcab eb lliw I“
.detcartsid eb ot desufer ehs dna
.eid ton dluow dna
,tnemugra eht tsol dah ehs taht wenk ireC ”?su
.deksa ilyeT ”?ireC“
.psarg etiuq t’ndid ehs gninaem a fo lluf ssenitpme tnangerp a tub
,nooccar eht sa llat sa won ,egdeh eht tub
dniw fo stsug yb ylno detautcnup teiuq a ni eta yehT
,ecneidua na ekil
.shtped eht morf deohce elpmet eht fo eciov eht
elpmet dercas siht nihtiw neddih erusaert eht thguos
.pih reh ta erow ehs drows eht fo hsalf leets dna revlis eht neve dna
.ekal niatnuom raelc a dna tserof erom tey dekoolrevo
.dias ilyeT ”,haey ,haeY“
.drows reh fo lemmop eht no detser rehto reH
”.gnorw neeb evah thgim I“
,saw ilyeT ta redluohs eht ta llat sa drazil wolley dna kcalb a
,daeh sti revo exa sti desiar tI
.tuo drows dna hgih daeh
,dednamed ilyeT ”?uoy era ohW“
,sraef dna sepoh rieht gnissucsid ,deklat yeht dna
.reh ot esolc ireC gnidloh
.suoicsnocnu nellaf dah nooccar eht taht yrrow ot nageb ilyeT taht
.gnorw saw gnihtemos ezilaer yletaidemmi ton did ilyeT dna
.rethgual gnisaet s’ireC ot ,deksa ilyeT ”?ti ezingocer llits neve ew lliW“ .yawa deraelc yllanif retniw eht nehw ekil kool dluow dlrow eht tahw dna ,dlihc gnimoc eht
,meht derongi ehS
.teef reh htaeneb gnikcub dnuorg eht
,swons eht deppots gnihton fi dna
”.remmuS fo waL eht kees I“
.remmus ni pu worg ll’eh dna
,regnil ton did ilyeT .elims tfos a htiw dednopser ireC dna
”.niaga ffo nur t’nod uoy fI“
.detaeper ehs ”?tahw woN“
,daorb sti otno ireC detfeh ylluferac dna
decnahne erifpmac eht fo htmraw eht
”?elddir eht taeper esaelp uoy dluoC“
ilyeT no dehgiew ecnelis ehT
.reh dlot dah elpmet eht tahw dna
gnol os rof edis s’ireC morf enog gnieb revo yteixna reh tub
”?gnihtyna yas uoy t’ndid yhW“ ”.yrros m’I“
.draytruoc eht fo sniur eht revo gnibmilc melborp on dah ilyeT .ti dnuora sniatnuom eht sa elbatummi dna elibommi sa deraeppa taht
egacbir a neeb evah dluow tahw rednu tsuj
.ireC ,dne eht t’nsaw sihT
taruggiz eht fo rebmahc lartnec eht ni eb dluow ezirp reH
,rehtom a saw ehS
.edisni retaw-noom fo elttob llams eht dna
.reh dniheb nwod dehsarc exa eht sa drawpu kcurts neht
,ecnatsiser on tem ehS
.woleb ssenkrad eht otni gnidael esacriats a gnilaever
”?ereh kees uoht tsod tahw ,erah elttiL“
;taerter dna uoht nruT
,rewop fo ecalp tneicna na
”.gninnigeb eht llits s’tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,rehtegot esolc dna dedworc werg seert eht erehw ,egdir eht fo mottob eht tA
,enohs anoroc eht tsuj litnu dedisbus ylwols neht
.srood eht ot resolc tperc
.sduolc mrots sseldne eht dniheb wolg tniaf a sa elbisiv ylerab
,desuap naidraug ehT
.ewa ni ilyeT ta pu gnirats
,reh ta tuo demoob elpmet ehT
:emac uoht ecnehw nruter ro
,ekal eht fo egde eht gnola htron yaw rieht detniop ireC
,srooM edisaeS eht fo ilyeT“ .edistuo eht ot yawllah eht desrevart ehs sa emit tsal eno
retaw-noom htiw dellif raj ssalg llams a dehsif ilyeT .kcalb hctip saw
,llihc eht tsniaga pu dellup dooh
.retaehtihpma eht ni dnas eht dehcuot swap reh sa noos sa dnuos a tuohtiw dehsinav esacriats ehT
cinut dna sevolg etihw htiw ni gnidnelb ruf etihw
,pmac eht fo thgis fo tuo dessap ehs sa derumrum ehs
,emit taht ni llef dna nesir dah cilbuper a dna shcranom owT
,dewollof taht ecnelis gnignir eht nI ”.erom ecno tub
.erutsop evisnefed a ni pu—
.slleps derettum ehs sa rennid rieht morf sdees revotfel eht gnirettacs
.dnas otni kcab elbmurc ot nageb tfel eht no esacriats ehT ”.ireC evas oT“
rehto hcae fo gnidnatsrednu peed a fo tuo nrob eno tub
.nwod dooh dna thgit dellup kaolc
.seye der-ybur reh tub gnihtyreve gnidih swodahs
.dnif dluoc ehs selbide revetahw rof seert eht hguorht degarof nooccar eht elihw
,dehctaw ehs sA
.shtnom eerht rof remmuS fo waL eht rof gnitnuh neeb dah yehT
.sehcni yb hcamots s’ilyeT gnissim
.teef reh gniggard
deelb ton did ti tub
.htuom reh denepo dah ilyeT erofeb ti tsol dah ehs wenk ehs tub
.llat teef net rallip a otni esor dnas ehT
,neeb dah ti naht reduol eciov sti
.flesreh fo demahsa yldlim kool ot ecarg eht dah ,noitcafsitas s’ilyeT ot ,ireC .elim a nur d’ehs hguoht sa gnitnap saw ehs
nehT“ .niaga ecno exa eht detfeh esroh ehT ”.t’nac I“
,ilyeT tsniaga dloc tlef ehS
,nrohtwah dna ,lezah ,yrrebpsar
,sselhtped s’ireC ni yawa reh gnihsaw sedit fo hsur elbativeni eht saw ti ,retfA
,tnemom tsal eht ta yaw eht fo tuo dils ehS
”noom“ dias ehs sa noos sa
.kcen tem redluohs erehw ydob sti gnitixe dna
,rehto hcae morf ecnatsid luftcepser a
erutaerc eht hguorht ylhtooms gnidils nopaew reh
.ereht gniworg efil eligarf ,llams eht gnileef
,tbuod a tuohtiw ,wenk ehS
.mrotsrednuht gnissap a ekil ecnelis otni delbmur eciov ehT
.sniatnuom eht fo ffo gniwolb dniw llihc eht otni gnitniuqs
.doolb dna hself fo erutaerc a no
”.erom eciwt ylno eeht ksa lliw I .oN“
.reh dnuora dniwlrihw a otni dedolpxe neht dna delwoh esroh ehT
”.em fo edisni nus a ekil
.smsirp latsyrc lacitnedi owt detaolf hcihw pota
”.rehtruf deecorp ot em tseb sdeen uoht
?kniht uoy od ,ti od ew naC“
,hcamots erab s’ilyeT revo detfird sdnah s’ireC fo enO
.noitome fo lluf dna diuqil
”,oN“ .detuohs ilyeT
,nus eht ro htrae eht morf cigam yna ward t’ndluoc I“
retniw siht dne ot seitinutroppo eerht dah evah tlahs uoht
,denrut dna dewolleb esroh ehT
.flesti htrae gnivil eht morf devrac rebmahc ralucric a saw dnoyeB
retaehtihpma eguh a saw rood eht dnoyeB
.flesreh ydaets ot llaw enots dloc eht tsniaga desserp dnah reh
,dias ireC ”,yrroS“
,edis s’esroh eht otni peed tib drows reH
,hcuot eht ot nezorf ylraen saw ireC
,deraelc dah sduolc eht
.ireC naht rellat ylbaeciton dna
.demoob elpmet eht
,ekal nezorf-flah eht fo sretaw krad eht otni elbmut gnoldaeh a spahrep ,petssim A
,yawa detlem wons eht ,spetstoof reh nI
.pu yaw eht lla gnimraw regnol on saw ehs ekil
roiretni s’elpmet ehT
”?gniklaw ’sruoh wef rehtona eganam uoy naC
.llaf ton did tub
rehto hcae dnuora depparw smra riehT
staes eht llif ot demees swodahs-hcrot gnirekcilf ehT
.erah eht ot esolc desserp
,nooccar eht llif htmraw reh fo emos tel ot deirt ehS
,taeh remmus a saw tI
”,gnorw s’gnihtemoS“
,namsilat lufrewop dna dercas A
htooms yrnosam dna seutats nellaf eht nrow dah sraey tneicna fo egassap ehT
htrof dewolf taeh dna
.yrassecen saw ygolopa on taht
.enola tfel saw ehs tub
.ireC tfel dah ilyeT erehw morf ekih s’ruoh na naht ssel
”?won ti xif ew od woh os ,yakO“
.raey eht fo elcyc eht erotser dna swons eht yawa wolb ot
.wollip s’ireC emoceb dah ehs yaw eht dnim ton did ehs tub
,romra reh fo rehtael deddap eht dna kaolc reh hguorht gnittuc
.niaga klat ot derevocer yltneiciffus saw ireC erofeb
”?evol yM“ ”?ilyeT .won toN“
,retniw gnisaecnu dna wons sseldne eb thgim edistuO
.ireC ,tiaw ot tnaw t’nod I“
”.os kniht I“ .desolc seye reh
,gnihtyna naht erom tuB
,dias ilyeT ”,os kniht I“
thgil htiw dezalb eye thgir reH
.espilce ralos a fo anoroc eht ekil
.detaler saw taht fi wenk ohw tub
noziroh eht ot tsomla deppid dah nus ehT
,pots dluow ireC
.egarrab gnignits eht tsniaga thgit desolc seye
,egdir gnol a pota doots ,nooccar eht ,nylaireC
.otni llaf dluoc eno taht seye fo tros eht erew yehT
.slatsyrc owt eht neewteb htrof dna kcab gnicnalg
thgin lla devom ylerab dah ireC
”?ecaf sdeen uoht taht slairt eht rof deraperp uoht trA
.sserac a ekil ,tfos eciov sti
dedeen ehs thgil eht fo lla dedivorp dna dnah reh ni mraw saw remmuS fo waL ehT
.desolc ydaerla seye reh ,derumrum ireC
,klaw reilrae rieht fo ssenllits elbanoinapmoc eht ton saw siht—
,yrrulf a deredisnoc eb ot hguone ylerab
nees dah ehs tahw denialpxe ehS
,detrats ilyeT ”…evas oT“
,sriats eht gnola ecnetsixe otni deppop semalf elprup dna eulB
,hcaer s’esroh eht edisni ylhtooms deppets ehs sa pord edalb reh fo tniop eht tel ehS
,sdnegeL fo kooB ehT ni dnuof eb nac krow esohw
,kaolc gnol fo elyts emas eht erow erah ehT
ria tlas-aes fo gnitsat
,revo dednuob ilyeT ,tsaeb kcap eht fo snier eht gnipporD
,seert eht revo dekop nus naw eht sa noos sa ffo tes yehT
ti llafeb llahs mrah on taht drow ruo tsah uohT“
,gninnips dna gnipmuj
,niaga dellac ilyeT ”!ireC“
,retniW sseldnE eht kcab hsup ot desu eb dluoc ti taht denialpxe dah ireC
,kcab reh no tub yaw yna gnipeels elbatrofmoc tlef regnol on ilyeT .redluohs reh tsniaga ni deltsen ireC sa deksa ilyeT ”?gniod ruoY“
.enog swodahs eht
.lemmop eht no dnah eno tpek ehs hguoht
,efil htiw gnitsrub dna dimuh
,gnizeerf fo ksir ta saw yldetbuodnu ohw
,siht xif llits ll’ew ,rehtegoT“
,raeppaer dluow esroh eht fi gnirednow
.gnirutrun saw ilyeT taht efil ynit eht ot dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.gniworg llits stnalp hgih-eenk otni detuorps dah detnalp dah ehs sdees tsrif eht
.ekal eht fo serohs eht no depmac yehT
,riah nworb gnol reh detsud eroM
”!peew dna seenk yht ot llaf eeht evah tsdluow sciryl eseht ,mrof lanigiro sti nI
.hcamots s’esroh eht otni peed edalb reh gnivird
,dnahffo reh ni tfola elttob eht gnidloH
”.remmuS fo waL ehT“
nwonknu noitnetni htiw
esolc ireC dleh ehs sa flesreh dlot ilyeT tahw si ,tsael ta ,tahT
,dehsiugnitxe lla erew sehcrot ehT
”?kcab htmraw eht gnirB
nwo rieht tsuj ton
:strap owt ni saw tI
.retniW sseldnE eht fo
,ekops ireC nehw
,yrrebkcalb fo egdeh ybbuts a otni werg stnalp eht sa dehctaw ehs
.thgin eht otni dehsinav nus eht fo syar tsal eht emit emas eht tuoba ta deppots wons ehT
,ylsuoicsnocnU ”?ybab eht s’woH“
,dnah s’ireC dezeeuqs ehS
,kaolc eht no gnilttes
.hcum yb ton tub erofeb naht rethgirb
,teiuq dna ytpme saw retaehtihpma eht