.lluh s’gir eht fo ffo gnignip stellub dna snug enihcam fo erif otaccats eht yb denioj erew
.draobhsad eht otni
.reh no hctarcs a t’nsaw ereht taht ees dluoc eh
.dray yrenifer eht fo tuo ylwols dereets dlareJ sa sriap gnitanretla ni nwod kcab sevlesmeht tes dna detfil sgel xiS
.droJ fo dlrowemoh sih gnitibro noom eht naht rethgirb raf
,mra llird eht fo hcaer nihtiw
a fo daetsni strops emertxe ni nees d’eh gnihtemos fo erom mih dednimer tsomla tI ?tahw morf dna
.elttab lairea eht sdrawot thgiarts gninnur saw noziroH dnA
?ni gnimoc senord eht fo senigne eht ti saw rO
.etamilc siht ni mraw reh peek ot niht oot yaw dekool taht tiuspmuj a dna teef rellams reh htiw neve
,daeh llird eht gnicalp emit sih koot eH
”?noitulos gnitegrat lecnac ton uoy nac yhW“
.decamirg revird xnyl ehT
”.nam ynapmoC ylluferac yrev netsiL“
.nooccar eht morf
.gab gnipeels eht ni otirrub a ekil pu depparw ,elba saw eh sa tseb sa reh morf yawa demriuqs eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dnecsed llird eht dehctaw dlareJ setunim gnidnirg-hteet lareves roF
”.sdnammoc cinagro sedecrepus esnefed tniop elissim-itnA“
”.mia rieht tsujda yltnatsnoc ot reusrup eht ecrof ,deusrup nehw gaz-giz dluohs uoy ,wonk uoY“
.dnopser ton did ehS
won rof reh htiw og ot deen d’eh ekil demees ti tub smialc s’namuhtsop eht tuoba erus t’nsaw llits eH
,teef reh ot yldrawkwa tpael ehs nehT
”.uoy deen I ,pu ekaw esaelp ,evila llits er’uoy fI“
eht morf rehtruf ,revewoH
pudliub eci eht bruc ot troffe yna
rof seye sih esolc ot mih gnitpmet yllacitonpyh
”.deen neve t’nod yeht taht gnihtemos rof etsaw a hcuS“ .dehgis ehS
?ti t’ndah kcab sretemolik neeb dah taht tub
,deviecer gninraW“
eht evas ot deen yeht ,tuB“
.decnuonna retupmoc ehT ”.detavitca slortnoc ecioV“
.noitom ni gir eht tes dna
”.tsrif meht ot pu hctac ot evom ot evah ll’eW
,taeH“ .demialc dlareJ
tsafkaerb sih fo deniamer tahw dehcter dna yawa denrut dlareJ
ton dnammoC“  .detuohs eH ”!gnikcatta potS“
.yks eht otni gnirats
gnixelf saw ti dna
.tsaerb elamef a ekil dekool
elttorht eht rof dehcaer eh yllacitamotua tsomlA
.dednopser dlareJ
.esle gnihtyreve decnuonorp d’ehs woh tcellocer ot deirt eh sa desuap eh
.stohs gnimocni eht diova ot devrews dna
,gnivom tsuj ton dna
.rotarepo gnivil a morf noitazirohtua tuohtiw gnirif ton tub
tcejbo eht dehctaw xnyl eht sa tuB
,sgel dna kcab reh rednu smra sih dehcni dna nooccar eht ot txen tlenk xnyl ehT
.gab gnipeels yvaeh a ni depparw saw eh taht ees ot ylno
,metsys ereiT eht ni noitats dna pihs yreve rewop ylisae dluoc ynapmoC eht ,si hturt eht tuB“ .deffins noziroH
.knat sag evissam s’gir eht tsniaga pu dedlof
”.yrgnuh sremotsuc rieht peek ot referp yeht tuB .igoL dna ,droJ
gniylf saw ti dna
,detnemgua“ .depsag eh ”,woH“
.nopu deppirt dah eh gniht eht sdrawot
,ydob s’noziroH fo thgis railimaf eht deweiv eH
.rood eht ni tes wodniw eht morf sknuhc eci wef a degdolsid mih dniheb tuhs rood eht gnimmals ylkciuQ
,dellik d’eh nosrep eht kool ot dah eh
,tahw rof uoy ta werht ew erawdrah fo tol a saw taht tub ,esneffo oN“
,pu gnitrats fo ssecorp suoirobal eht nageb gir gninim ehT
enahte fo loop wollahs a mih dewohs margonos ehT
.llew sa gninnur detrats dna teef sih ot delbmuts eh dessap tnemom ehT
pihc retrats eht gnittols erofeb mih dniheb rood eht demmals dna hgis ytsim a tuo tel eH
,noitcesdim s’nooccar eht morf gnimoc lworg a pu dekcip srae detfut s’dlareJ
,mih fo daeha deggoj ehs sa etinifedni demees animats reH
.yllacitnarf dnuora dekool eh no gniog saw tahw gnirednow dna desufnoC
.esnopser ni deksa noziroH
.mood lleps dluoc taht gnikcarc fo sngis yna rof gnitiaw
eil gir siht tel dah ohw scinahcem ynapmoC eht desruc eH .denaorg dna
.revo meht pilf ot nwod dehcaer dna
”.tih a ekaf dluoc I hguone esolc
.railimaf dednuos eciov eht thguoht eh srekaeps eht hguorht nevE
.eci eht otni knis boj sih gnihctaw tsuj
,tfel enord eno ylno saw ereht stnemom nI
.moor ekam ot kcab rehtruf
”.uoy ot tuo tropsnart a tog ynapmoC eht emit eht yb dilos nezorf eb d’uoY
,emit a ta pets eno ,eci eht revo edorts ylluferac tac ehT
.ezorf yeht erofeb sreksihw sih morf timov fo spord eht ekahs ot gniyrt ,yldliw
.redisnoc ot desuap dlareJ
,dehsarc dah reilf eht erehw ot revo kcab derednaw eye siH
.sgir nezod a llif
ydob esotamoc s’noziroH
erats ot noitnetta s’dlareJ werd mih dniheb senibrut fo dnuos ehT
,elissim a erew uoy thguoht retupmoc ehT“
.tnedicni tuohtiw
.deugirtni erom noos tub
.etis llird eht ot sruoh ruof
dniw gnitib eht tsniaga
.rehtona eno dnuora gnivaew dna gnibbob tub
.sduolc eht ssorca gnikaerts remmiks ynapmoC a was eh taht raews tsomla dluoc eh
.nooccar namuhtsop eht htiw ecap peek ot gniyrt fo setunim erem retfa gnitnap flesmih dnuof xnyl ehT
.elissim a saw dediced dah ti gniht eht rof noitulos gnirif a dnuof dna senord rehto eht derongi ti sa gat
tahw ni tuo deglub tiuspmuj etihw rieht tfel eht no hguoht
.ekops dna lufhtuom reh dewollaws ehS
”?RV noitcudni laruen esu reve uoy ,haeY“
senord rediar eht kcart ot gnileviws nug AA s’gir eht ees dluoc eh hcaer s’mra ni ylraen saw nibac eht emit eht yB
ot hguone ,loop repeed raf a saw ereht ”erohs“
.erofeb gir siht nevird dah ohw rednow ot emit dlareJ gnivig
,retal emit etanimretedni na ekow dlareJ  .tuo dekcalb dna
,dnuorg eht ffo esir teef dnih s’gir eht was eh nehT
eh os selop s’rutruS ot esolc siht sdrib yna t’nerew ereht niatrec ylriaf saw eH .yks eht ni
”?taht laets ot tnaw ew dluow yhw woN“
,tenalp eht ta pu dekool xnyl ehT
nellaf dah erugif eht erehw gnirats
.deilper eh ”,srediaR“
.ecaf sih otno gnilbmuts mih tnes dna
deppots erif nug enihcam eht ytinrete na ekil demees tahw retfA
.wons gnimaets eht otno
eh retem llif knat eht ta ecnalg erom eno htiW .yal llits dna
tsaf mih gnidloh esproc eht ees ot kcab dekool dna dnuorg eht ffo flesmih detfil xnyl ehT  .dnuorg eht ot mih gard dna elkna eht yb mih barg dnah a tlef eh dnuora nips dluoc eh erofeB
.moc.sserpdrow.muirepmiarap ta
wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ekam ot noisiced ysae na saw ti
,tlef llits yeht mraw woh yb desirprus saw eH
”.troppus efil eht etelped
?stcartnoc eninoel s’ynapmoC eht fo tuo yaw emos dnuof d’yeht fi ro
emac tohs tsal taht gniht dooG
.won od ot tahw niatrecnu ,ezorf xnyl ehT
”?ni evac ot gniog saw eci eht wenk uoY“ .deksa eH
”.ekawa er’uoy ,doog hO“
tsim fo duolc hsidder a tuo gnidnes dna senarbmem gniw rieht gnidderhs
,mra llird eht gnitaoc eci tuoba sgninraw der htiw detadnuni saw eh pu detrats sneercs eht sa noos sa tsomla tuB
”?seildneirF eht htiw er’uoY“
…fo ezis eht redluob a ,eci
,stnioj s’mra eht morf gnignah selcici eht ta dekool xnyl ehT
.yllufepoh deksa eH ”?noziroH“
,tuo ti gninohpis nageb dna
ega tsol a fo rednow gnivil a fo elcatceps eht hctaw ot tsuj tnemom a rof deppots dlareJ
.pu dekool noziroH
,niatnuom a fo edis eht dettops eh mih dniheB
.gninnur tpek eh tub ,dica citcal dna noitavirped negyxo morf maws noisiv siH
”.od ot ereh tuo emac I tahw s’ti dnA“ .dias ehs
,dnuorg eht ffo xnyl eht detfil ,etispmac eht dessorc dah nooccar eht knilb dluoc eh erofeB  ”!luhg a er’uoY“
tohs gnitteg tuoba deirrow t’nsaw eh taht won
.deilper retupmoc ehT ”.dezingocer
.srab noitar erom tuo llup dna dnik emos fo kcap a revo dneb reh dehctaw dlareJ
.nar dna tuo deliab revird s’eno rehto eht rednu tnew eno nehW
ecaf eht ni ,yllanoitnetninu
,retsum dluoc eh sa
.elbaliava neeb dah eno siht dna ,erofeb yad eht ecnanetniam rof ni enog dah gir lamron siH .neppah thgim
eci retaw eht rednu diuqil nobracordyh digirf eht otni knas ti tuB
,ssam fo retnec eht ni erauqs reilf eht thguac tohs txen s’nug AA ehT  ”!nosrep a s’tI
”?efil rof dragersid lausac rieht morf edisA“
”.margorp reidlos repus fo dnik emoS
”snoziroH enahtE“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
.detrons nooccar ehT  ”.em tae t’noD“
.degdod ylerab reilf eht taht tohs rehtona ffo gnirif
htiw nekops s’ehs nrows evah dluoc eH
.deksa eH ”?su pleh ynapmoC eht t’nac yhW“
”?gnineppah s’tahW ?yhW“
.eci eht otni nael
.slortnoc llird eht pu detrats dna boj sih fo trap ”gnitseretni“ eht rof riahc sih ni deleviws eH
.evarg eht sa llits
”.efil namuharap rof dragersid ynapmoC lacipyT“
.meht ot txen dnuorg eht no gniyal liat dekcos egral a deciton eh tub ,elgna siht morf seiceps ro xes llet ton dluoc eH
,eci ffo gniraelc dna srediar eht ffo gnithgif emit fo tol a tsol d’eH
.gir sih fo nibac eht otni debmilc eh sa derevihs dlareJ  namssierK leoJ yb ”snoziroH enahtE“   yojne esaelP
.ecaf s’nooccar eht ta ylsuoituac dekop eh
,flah ni rab rehto eht deppans ehS
,edis thgir eht no serutaef yna tuo ekam ot dedderhs ylhguoroht oot
”.no s’ti elihw uoy kcah nac yehT
.gniksa morf pleh t’ndluoc eH ”?uoy era ohW“
mra llird eht ot del taht yrtnag eht sdrawot denrut dlareJ
,relevart wollef ruoy
thgil fo skceps nezod a flah
.dray eht evael ot tsuj setunim net koot tI  ”.taht regoR“
.delkcarc oidar ehT
”!elissim a ton s’tahT“
!tius thgilf a s’tahT“
.feiler retsasid rof sdop raludom evah senord yldneirF
,srae dnuor ,tuons detniop a ,daeh derruf ylthgil a htiw namow A
.knat sih llif ot hguone ylerab
.erofeb gniht fo dnik taht nees d’eh erehw derebmemer xnyl ehT
.retal ti rednop ot detnaw eh fi
.mra eerf reh htiw
.sgel nekorb yltnecer htiw enoemos rof deeps evisserpmi ta nar dna
litnu gir elgnis a no revird a tup ynapmoC eht yllausU
,tfarc kcatta erup era slortap riehT“ .deilper noziroH
.lufegnev tlef yeht fi nalc rieht ot noitutitser yap ot gnivah ekil ton thgim ynapmoC eht tub
.ees t’ndluoc dlareJ gnihtemos sdrawot kool ot daeh reh denrut ehS
”?cificeps erom eb uoy dluoC .taht teg t’ndid I ,yrroS“
.deddon noziroH  ”?gir a saw tahT“
,tnemom a rof desufnoc saw dlareJ
”!noitulos gnitegrat lecnaC“
,knuhc eci eht dehcnup ylirgna
.rutruS no dewolla ylgnigdurg ynapmoC eht
.dexelprep dna deveiler htob mih tfel was eh tahw dna
.eci fo gnipporctuo na no gnippirt tsomla
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
,gir gniknis eht morf yawa denrut
,noitator s’llird eht morf snoitarbiv eht htiw koohs gir ehT
,erom yna nur ot elbanu
,drow tsal taht no tup ehs gnawt retleB eht deton dlareJ  ”?setariP
dloh ograc s’enord eht otni reh gnuws eh tnurg a htiW
,yawa edorts ehs sa thguoht fo niart sih gnitpurretni ,tuo dellac ehS
.pu llif knat eht dehctaw dna
.reilf denwod eht fo noitcerid eht ni
,mih dnuora gnilcric enord eht was dna pu dekool
ksa ot xnyl eht gnitpmorp
,meht gniodnu dna gnidnif erofeb gab gnipeels eht ot spsalc eht rof delbmuf eH .deksa dlareJ
?syad eseht dluow ohw tub ,deid eh woh eb ot siht detcepxe t’ndah eH
.yllacitamotua tsomla dewollof eh dna
gnivohs yldrawkwa ,enord eht otni debmilc eH
eganam dluoc tnemrag paehc eht tseb sa akrap sih delaes eh ,ecnayonna elbatciderp fo naorg a htiw
,teef s’gir eht htaeneb gninnur kcarc a deips seye sih nehw dnoces a rof desuap eH
.deyortsed stegrat lla“
erofeb tnemom a rof gnitiaw ereht doots eH
.elbisualp ylgnibrutsid dednuos dias ehs gnihtyreve tub
eht ni dednepsus redluob a ot txen gir eht dekrap dah eh
.epahs ekil-xob a otni sevlesmeht delbmessa deppord ti slenap eht sa dednopser enord ehT
”?uoy od ,esoht fo erom yna evah uoy esoppus t’nod I“
resolc flesreh gard ot gniyrt elihw
stuodaer cihpargonos eht revewoH
,mra llird eht dehcaer eh emit eht yb leets eht sa nezorf sa leef ot gnitrats saw dlareJ
.no deunitnoc dna
.mih dniheb snialp nezorf eht morf tnereffid on dekool taht eci fo dleif a sdrawot wodniw eht tuo dekool eH .”devirra evah uoy“ decnuonna tolipotua eht dna pots a ot detloj gir eht sa ekawa deknilb dlareJ  …tnemom a tsuj
,niaga rood eht esolc ot gnirehtob tuohtiw evolg sih devomer dna rood eht nepo deknay xnyl eht yllacitnarF
taht revewoh ,ecivres fo tuo nekat saw gir eht ro revird eht rehtie
.eci kciht-sretem otni gnidnirg
ylleb s’enord eht morf dlofnu ot nageb slenap fo riap a dehctaw eh sA
”.enahte fo sretilolik derdnuh a tuoba dnA“  ”?doof fo solik 09
,srekrow rieht pu gnitaeh no
”.epyt ym ton er’uoY“
.srekaepsduol sti morf etaname eciov a draeh eh dna
.reddal gnidraob s’gir eht morf deppord eh sa dnuos ”hcnurc“ tfos a htiw eci eht tih staelc siH
.gnimoc esle eno on saw ereht erus ekam ot tsuj
.derehtalb dlareJ ”,tuB“
.niaga meht dereggirt dna slortnoc llird eht ot kcab denrut eh hgis a htiW .tsaf
.yliraropmet eussi eht delttes kcolc eht ta ecnalg A
,rutruS no egalliv dna ytic yreve sulp
.eci fo hctap taerg eht revo tuo dehcaer dna dedlofnu mra llird eht naorg dna kaerc taerg a htiW
”.yltcefrep gnikrow era enim ,ees nac uoy sA“
”!detceted elissim elbissop“
”.kcol tegrat eht ffo tuhs em tel t’ndluow dna
.deksa eH ”?noziroH“
”snoziroH enahtE“ saw sihT
.tsalb taht devivrus dah reilf eht ylekil t’nsaw tI
,rab noitar reh fo etib rehtona koot nooccar ehT
tahw htiw tekcos wolloh a gnilaever ,dileye reh denepo ehS
diuqil fo ekal egral a fo ecneserp eht mih dewohs
.sih otni ecaf deksam reh tsurht dna
,ssem der a saw tsehc s’ydob ehT
.denialpxe nooccar ehT
.meht tpecretni ot gnivom si lortap ynapmoC a yletanutrofnU“
ti wenk eh erofeB
,yks eht fo tuo tohs d’eh namow eht fo yruf sseleye eht otni derats eh sa ezorf dlareJ
,ynapmoC eht htiw llits saw revird tsal sti fi flesmih ot derednow eH
,temleh reh evomer ot yrt dna kcab nrut ot rehtehw no dnim sih pu ekam ot gniyrt saw eh sA
”.wonk uoy ygolonhcet tsol yltcaxe t’nsi noisuF“
,erofeb gir ralucitrap siht desu t’ndah eh tub ,sevlesmeht nar ylegral sreklaw lassoloc ehT
,yrtnag eht evoba thgieh eenk ot toob ediw sih detfil xnyl ehT
elgna esicerp eht ta daeh llird eht demia ,ylluferac ,ylwols dna
”.tsael ta shtnom wef tsap eht roF“
feiler fo hgis a dehtaerb dlareJ
.detuohs xnyl ehT
.ygoloib etarucca-flah htiw
,srellird doog dedeen
,yrtnag eht otni tsrif-ecaf gnimmals diova ot emit ni gniliar eht gnihctac ylerab tsuj ,pets htruof sih no deppils eH
.esnopser ni yrc gnilgrug a gniviecer dna temleh reh ffo gnitcelfed ylno tub ,daeh s’esproc gnivil eht ta gnikcik ,detuohs eH ”!og teL !og teL“
truS tnaig sag eht tub noziroh eht dnoyeb deppils ydaerla dah nus eht
.denialpxe retupmoc ehT
”?setsaw eht si siht ekiL ?tahW“
.ybraen dnuorg eht no gniyl temleh nekorb a dettops dna
”.elbarevocerri yllatot mih tfel aimrehtopyh eht erofeb pu mih dekcip ew dna mih dettops senord ruo fo eno yletanutroF
.nur daed a otni ekorb ehS
”.tiusgniw a ni sgir rieht fo eno fo pot no pord ot ydobemos detcepxe yeht kniht t’nod I“
enord rotor-tlit egral a ta
mra sih htiw tuo kcurts dlareJ
”.taht wonk I t’noD“
smra sih htiw htgnerts gniydnu reh ffo dnef ot
.efil eritne sih ni nur reve dah eh naht retsaf ,nar eH
”.noom siht no gnihtyreve srewop tI“
,gel reh rof kcab dehcaer dna
.yawa sretem eerht ton gnirevoh
,maets gnisir fo semulp dnuora evaew erugif dalc-etihw eht dehctaw eH
.gniniart ecnis dekcilc yllanoitnetni t’ndah eh nottub a dekop eh flesmih gnisruC
.talf ylddo dna ,desolc saw dileye thgir reh taht deciton eh esolc saw eh taht woN
taht selgna larutannu ta detsiwt erew sgel reH
.gab gnipeels eht fo eerf mra sih delggirw eh sa
.ylluferac erom kaeps ot deirt dna htaerb peed a koot eH
”!oot ereh s’ynapmoC eht ,tihS“
,deifirret tsrif ta ,tnecsed s’gniht degniw egnarts eht dewollof dlareJ
sesag elbaulav eht fo yna gnitsaw t’nerew sevitucexe eht
.niaga edistuo og ot flesmih deraperp dna
.dnuorg eht gnittih stellub dnuora gnitluasremos dna gnipael
sdleif etihw sseldne eht sa pan a gnikat deredisnoc ylgnorts eH
dlareJ .wons eht no kcab reh no delwarps
,dnuorg eht no dial noziroH
,daehrevo nretnal a ekil dewolg
,ydob eht morf sretem evif eci eht gniniats srettalps doolb eht dnuof eH
muminim ta taht dediced eh noitaredisnoc fo etunim a retfA
.tnemgdelwonkca sih gnittimsnart erofeb desuap dlareJ
deraelc ti nehw dna
sdomoib xnyl nesohc d’eh taht ,niaga ecno ,detterger eH
,edis thgir eht no derettahs neeb dah temleh ,reh ,riehT
,mih erofeb dehcterts
.nibac eht ot kcab nur ot denrut dna
.tsugsid ni kcab tpael dna kcab rieht otno ydob eht werht ylkciuq xnyl ehT .tew dna
,dnuorg eht ot despalloc eh yllanif dna reverof nur ton dluoc eh tuB
,hself nwo rieht ezilabinnacotua taht shtnysokuel gninoitcnuflam evah sluhG“ .dias ehS
.slortnoc eciov desu reve ydobon yhw yldipar dednimer gnitteg saw dlareJ
.demrifnoc noziroH
”?ton ro gnimoc uoY“
.epahs otni kcab ti decrof ehs ekam dluohs senob gnihtyna naht latem gnidneb ekil erom dnuos a htiw
.sllaw nibac eht yb delffumnu
,kaeps ot os ”tiurf gnignah-rewol“
.yllacitpeks deksa dlareJ ”!?ton yhW“
.ees dluoc eh nottub ”erif“ yreve dehsup dna neercshcuot eht ta sregnif digirf sih debbats eh
”.tol a nialpxe dluow tahT“
,floWcaM boR si sihT
tnorf reh otno revo kcab deppilf ehS
,gniraew saw nooccar eht tiuspmuj deniats-der eht dezingocer eh sa denediw seye s’xnyl ehT  ”.meht fo tser eht ot deltitne m’I kniht I ,nwod em tohs uoy retfa hsinelper ot evah I ssamoib hcum woh nevig tuB“
.etadommocca dluoc senob namuharap on
noitcif-ecneics setirw ohw ,namssierK leoJ yb
,mih sdrawot llef tcejbo detagnole llams a sa gir eht morf ffo gnireev saw enord egral yllausunu nA
,deedni ,saw ti taht mrifnoc ot
?dniw eht taht saW
,drawrof reklaw taerg eht dehsup dna slortnoc ytilibom s’gir eht ot kcab deleviws dlareJ
.yllacitsacras dias noziroH
”.emoh kcab yaw eht lla uoy yrrac ot evah d’I fi gnirednow saw I“
,edis eht ot gninrut daeh sih thguorb dnuos gnihcnurc A
.yad eht fo tser eht rof ecaf sih no timov nezorf htiw laed ot gnivah fo raef fo tuo
.mih sdrawot ylizal detfird enord ehT ”.hguone riaF“
,kcab ti dloh t’ndluoc eh emit sihT
.ni liat reh fo dne eht dehsup yllufecargnu dna
,seidob laitselec rof tsaf rehtar gnivom erew srats eht fo hcnub a taht was eh pu peek ot delggurts dlareJ sA
.rab eht flah tuo dleh dna dlareJ ot txen nwod dettauqs noziroH ”.serugif tahT“
,tuo dellac eH ”!tiaW“
,kcab kool ot gnirad ton ,emac eh yaw eht kcab nar dna denrut dlareJ  !mih rof thgir
toof detoob a htiw wons fo hctap a yawa tpews eh ylsuoituaC
ruf reivaeh sti htiw drapoel wons fo daetsni
,desivda eb 32 giR“
ym fo snoitpecrep yrosnes eht tuo tuc em stel stnalpmi ym fo enO“
.pac eci sti gnirettahs tuohtiw llew eht etartenep ot
.ylkciuq erom pu mih llif dluow erusserp retaerg eht tub
.yrenifer eht fo raelc er’uoy sa noos sa oidar ruoy ffo tuhS“  ”?ecivda yna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
dnuorg eht fo tuo gnikcits gnihtemos no thguac swap ekil-eohswons sih nehw dleifelttab eht sdrawot nur ot eb thgim ti diputs woh gnizilaer tsuj saw xnyl ehT
.sehtolc yvaeh sih otni sregnif dewalc gniggid
,wols yllufniap saw yrtnag nezorf eht ssorca gnipmots
,dnuora kool rehtona koot dlareJ  ”?gnimoc uoy“
,dnuos wen a yb denioj erew dna demuser ylkciuq stsalb s’nug AA eht tuB
a htiw tcejbo gnidnecsed eht gnithgilhgih retupmoc gnitegrat eht
,eci eht ni dednepsus gnipporctuo ykcor a revo deppots eH
.desolc rood yab ograc eht sa no emac thgil mid A
.noitseuq a mih deksa ehs yltcerid gnirewsna fo daetsnI
.nibac eht otni deelb ot detrats yllanif dah taeh etsaw s’metsys evird eht ffo ti hctiws ot derebmemer eh emit eht yB
dna ffo kcab ecafretni eciov eht gnihctiws ,dehgis xnyl ehT  ”.deyortsed
.oga keew a ereh tuo sgir owt dah yehT“
.senord gniniamer eht nwod gnitoohs dehsinif nug eht elihw
,wons eht ni nwod-ecaf yal reilf ehT
.htaerb a ekat ot pots ton derad eh tub ,nar eh sa erom dna erom tnap ot decrof flesmih tlef eH
.rab noitar reh fo flah rehto eht pu dehcnurc nooccar ehT
,tnemom a tub rof reh fo weiv sih derucsbo wons deziropav fo tej a nehT
nwod kcab ti decrof tub taorht sih ni esir elib eht tlef dlareJ
,efil sih rof deracs yllufthgir woN
daeh sih koohs dlareJ
.lluks dna hself der delgnam gniwohs
.noisolpxe retfa noisolpxe ni pu thgil srats elibom eht was
”?dloh ograc eht otni ydob ym daol uoy dluoc ,dnim t’nod uoy fi woN“
”.gnimocni si pukcip ruO“
?erew ew uoy llet yeht did tahw ,oS“
sgniw suonarbmem fo tes a dedlofnu
detnurg reilf denwod ehT
.pu kool ot derad tsomla dlareJ dna
,namssierK leoJ yb
,on tub ,remraw eb wohemos
,emarf enipus sih pu flesreh deggard dna
,kcohs ni ereht doots dlareJ  ”.dezingocer ton dnammoC“
?revird roirp s’gir eht ot deneppah dah tahw taht saW
tsael ta tops dna pu ecnalg ot deneppah eh nehw eci kciht-retemiced fo knuhc suoicinrep ylralucitrap a no gnikrow saw dlareJ
ti nurtuo t’ndluoc eh taht won gniwonK
.gir sih sdrawot kcab ezag sih werd skcarc fo seires duol a neht dnA
daeh sih denrut eh seye sih morf wons eht gnikahS
gir eht dna evom gnorw eno
.elcici tseraen eht ta yldetaeper dekcahw eh sa
.ydob nwo ym erew yeht fi sa selcihev lortnoc yletomer dna ydob cinagro
stsalb s’nug nwo sih sa tsuj
staelc htiw nevE
gnikam tuohtiw gnol os eldi
.ylyrd dias ehs ”,seY“
”.gniog teg dluohs eW“
”ytiroirp lacitirc“
.roolf latem derevoc wons eht sdrawot nwod decnalg dna
,pam s’tolipotua eht ta decnalg eH
,noitca ot deltratS
.rab noitar fo dnik emos gnitae saw seye htob dnuora selcric krad dna
”.yltnecer rotces ruoy ni ytivitca rediar fo stroper neeb s’ereht
ecrof hcum sa htiw nwod ti thguorb dna
.mih fo daeha kaerts enord eht ees ot ylno
,mra na tfil ot detrats dlareJ
,mih sdrawot dnecsed dna dnuora gniws ti dehctaw eH
,namuharap egnarts siht deveileb eh fi wonk t’ndid eH
ydaerla despalloc t’ndah ti fi elihw a ereht neeb evah tsum ti taht dedulcnoc eh tub
.llab a otni gnilruc erofeb kcab rood eht deknay dna ekans a ekil
.seciffo reknub detalusni-llew rieht ni deyats yeht elihw
.wons eht otni tuo llips ot tac eht gniwolla
ot demees ti sa reklaw citnagig eht dnuora esor duolc ropav A
ynapmoC truS eht yhw nosaer elohw eht ,trap ykcirt eht saw sihT
dluow gninim nobracordyh taht noisserpmi eht dah d’eH
!won gniknis yletinifed saw ti
,mih deussi dah ynapmoC eht reparcs citsalp llams eht ta nwod decnalg
,yllacitamotua gnirif nug eht fo noisolpxe eht htiw gnar srae siH
.srehto eht morf tnereffid yltbus saw ti eye deniart sih ot
ti edam dah ohw rednow mih gnikam
”.ylpmoc ot elbanU“  .niaga deirt eH
.yrtnag eht ssorca ylluferac erom gnilffuhs deunitnoc dna
”.taht tbuod fo dnik I“
.os erom ton fi ,sgniw tfarcria dedderhs ti sa ylisae sa hself derhs dluoc ti ,ria-dim lenparhs otni trapa tsrub taht sretsinac evisolpxe derif nug AA ehT
dluow tI .pihs a no gnihtyna nrub t’nac uoY .spihsecaps rof muitirt
.ssap yreve htiw rehtruf gnidnecsed
etats retupmoc eht draeh eh nehw eirever sih fo tuo gnippans ylnO
”!nosrep a erew uoy wonk t’ndid I“
,deppots ehS ”.raf toN“
.sseldrager ecnatsid tnacifingis a tub ,os ro secap evissam nezod a tsuj
.gniksa neve tuohtiw sllig eht ot pu su deggua senord sti dna pihs drauG laredeF dlo na dnuof werc yM“
.rewsna ot kcab gninrut erofeb rab a nwod deplug nooccar ehT
.dniw eht ni gniwolb spalf tiusgniw
…esimed elbativeni sih gnitpecca erofeb
”?em evas uoy did yhw dnA“
.temleh reh fo rosiv derettahs eht rednu gninetsilg hteet erovinrac ydoolb
,ffo kcarc ot ti fo ekalf llams a gnisuac
”.gnitraped won ria nooccaR“
.deilper rehctapsid ehT
,nees reve dah eh enord ro elissim yna ekilnu
.ezigolopa ot deirt eH
…mih gnitae erofeb mih htiw gniyot
,ydob s’noziroH ta kcab derats dlareJ
espalloC eht fo smlifoloh nezod a derebmemer eh sa demaercs dlareJ
.esolc os saw eh taht won ti tfil ot tnatculer
.deganam dah rehcaet myg on ekil mih gnitavitom mih dniheb sdnuos gnikcarC
gnimaercs mrala dehctip-hgih ylgniyonna na
.ytreporp rieht detluassa dah ohw rediar a yfitnedi ot tnaw thgim ynapmoC eht dnah rehto eht nO
.htaed tnaem pots oT
.thgir tsuj elgna eht gnitteg tneps eh setunim ynam woh rettam on ,knat eht llif ot sruoh ekat dluow ti erusserp retaerg eht htiw neve
eldnah rood eht rof dehcaer eh dnuos eht yb detneirosiD
eh dna ,elttab lairea gniunitnoc eht ta pu dekool eH
.teef ediw sih ot delbmarcs xnyl ehT
.ecnetsixe tnaifed reh htiw erawdrah yratilim nredom gnitnuat
.llird eht trats ot hguone tnedifnoc tlef eh ,yllaniF
.deggeb eh ”,esaelP“
.tsevrah ot mih diap ynapmoC eht taht enahte dna enahtem fo dnelb eht ylniatrec tsomla ,htaenrednu
detseggus dlareJ
.gir eht morf yawa raf
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dehgis noziroH  .dedda eH
.noisiced drah a t’nsaw ti taht detpecca eh ecnO
.dednopser eh sa smetsys snopaew yratnemidur s’gir eht dekcehc ylkciuq eH
.daehrevo gnignah tnaig sag eht ta bmuht a detniop nooccar ehT
,ydob eht ot txen nwod tlenk dlareJ
.eci eht otni evord sekips tnulb eht sa kcarc gniyfsitas a gnignirb
.mih dewohs ti tahw ta yltnetni derats dna neercs eht ot pu tpael dlareJ
.flesmih ekil tnecca naidroJ a
.woleb eci eht ot stnemgarf gnikoms ni llef dna tsrub srats eht fo eno dehctaw eh sA
”?em gnivas erew uoy dnA“
.stnalpmi reh fo emos eb tsum desoppus eh hcihw ,ezis reh rof yvaeh ylgnisirprus saw ehs
,dias retupmoc ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
.kcab eht no gninetsilg retsilb dellif-sup a ekil dekool
,dnuorg eht ot delbmut yeht sa
.eye nworb reh otni derats eh sa doolb deird fo stnanmer eht llems dluoc eH
llits saw ereht elihw dleif sag a otno raf taht gnirutnev dnemmocer ton did sger ytefas ynapmoC
yab eht fo dne etisoppo eht no
”.raey a rof yteicoS yldneirF eritne eht rewop dluoc ereht pu truS yddad gib fo tuo gninohpis si ynapmoC eht muitirt eht fo retilorcim a dnA“  ”…senigne ,sthgil
.akrap sih ni gnirevihs ,esab morf yawa degdurt eh sa ruoh na flah rof no oidar eht tpek dlareJ
.ecaps regnessap ro ograc on
.snobracordyh elbammalf fo duolc a ni eci eht otni knis dluow
.ecalp otni kcab meht ekahs ot gniyrt saw ehs fi sa ,reh dniheb ria eht ni yldliw delialf sgel nekorb reH
noitazinagro nairatinamuh eno eht fo noitnem eht ta esirprus ni deknilb dlareJ
”?rehtruf hcum woH“
.mih dehcaorppa dna pu doots ehS
.emit eht eb dluow won detsixe ti fi tub ,erofeb nees reven d’eh noci na rof neercs eht dnuora dekool eh yllacitnarF
tupni sih rof deen yna tuohtiw flesti yb gninnur peek dluow ti taht derugif
”.kcab gnitoohs tuoba yhs eb t’nod dnA“
.dennalp yllanigiro sa esab ot kcab meht tropsnart dna gir eht ot kcab meht yrrac ot dnats dluoc eh fi wonk t’ndid eH
.nepo rood eht gnuws dna
tpmetta tsal elituf a edam eH
”.erew uoy sa lufetargnu sa“
”,noziroH em llac nac uoY“
.edirts gnikaerb neve tuohtiw deilper ehS
”?saw fo pot no dekrap uoy ssam cillatem taht kniht uoy did tahW“
.ylgnitivni nepo gnuh rood s’erutcurts xob ehT
”.wonk t’nod I“  ”?uoy era
…a ekil ,ecived lacinahcem
.niaga dnuora denrut eh gnikniht tuohtiw dna
golb sserpdroW rieht ro
sdaol trohs rof seitlanep s’ynapmoC eht gniredisnoC
,selaT dnuoB yb snamuharaP fo edirP ehT fo rohtuA
tnemom a rof ,dennuts ,ereht dial dlareJ
.mih dniheb dnuos gnikcarc a draeh eh
.rutruS ot gnitargime sih nopu meht dereffo dah ynapmoC eht nehw
,ti dniheb gniliart emulp evird a fo ngis on ees dluoc eH
.enord eht hguorht dias ehs ”,seY“  ”?yako er’uoy ,oS“
kcab deleviws eh ylkciuq neht
.mih rof thgiarts gnidaeh skcarc dna enahte gnitaropave fo duolc a saw tfel saw ereht lla
.edih ot erehwon ,eci etihw krats fo dleif nepo na no erew yeht tub ,etuor epacse elbissop a rof dnuora dekool eH
.tnemssarrabme ekil demees tahw htiw mih deppord ehs dna
.lwarc a ot ssergorp nwo sih gniwols ,detnap dlareJ
”.ssamoib tnemecalper fo ecruos tneinevnoc tseraen eht tuo kees ot meht gnivird
dedda noziroH
krow ot kcab teg ot dah eh thgindim erofeb enod boj eht teg ot detnaw eh fi
?od ot gniog saw eh tahw gnirednow
llab llams a otni flesmih lruc ot deirt dlareJ  ”.epyt suolaej eht eb nac dneirflrig yM .ereht ni ysdnah oot teg ot ton yrT“
.srorroh sti dna
.eci suorehcaert fo liart a gnidih
wohemos saw ehs taht ytilibissop eht tuo elur t’ndid ti hguohT
.resolc emac eh sa sloop nezorf ot skcelf der llams morf gniworg
,evah thgim yeht ylimaf yna ot revo ti nrut dna ydob eht revocer ot elba  eb thgim eH
”?taht droffa dluoc I ekil kool I oD“
ytiniffAruF ro yrruFoS no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,etis llew eht ot pam eht no egnar niatnuom a gniees derebmemer eh