,gnihcaorppa erew slammam detius owT
,relab yah citamotua sih ffo gniwohs noclaf a fo taht neewteb dezeeuqs gniht ynit a
.noitcifnaf dna acitore fo esod ytfeh a htiw gnola
.edaced a naht erom fo tset eht doots dah secived eseht fo enon
.dworc s'riaf eht fo ytimynona eht otni
,ylper ot detrats haisoJ "…si ti sa tub
tseb reh toN .tiucric eht riaper ot gnireknit fo setunim wef a koot ylno tI
.snoitseuq ynam oot ksa t'ndluow eh yllufepoH
;ecalp fo tuo ylbidercni dekool htoob siH .eno tpecxE
.niaga gniog ti tog ev'I kniht I tub
selkcunk sih htiw par a ti gnivig
,tiucric dedaolrevo na tsuJ
.gniyas saw enoemos ",noitacilppa lairtsudni sah ygolonhcet siht decnivnoc ton m'I"
.egamad eht tcepsni ot gnisuoh s'nocaeB eht nepo gnippop
.emoh tisnarT reh rof noitacol laedi na detneserp
"?ti llac uoy od tahW .yvoorg saw tahT"
.enif eb dluow eH
.emoh reh teg dluow ti dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.yrotcaf eht ni boj a ekat tsuj dluohS
.wollof ot selur erew erehT …llits tub
.s'haisoJ fo raer eht ta devirra ehs litnu spets reh decarter niraM
.esu lairtsudni rof elbatius level a ot desaercni eb dluoc ti
"?enihcam ym ta kool
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,oneR enacrA yb
.redistuo na sa reh tops thgim
ni demooz niraM ".ylesolc
.yalpsid-oloh eht no debmuht dna
.htoob eht fo tnorf eht morf tnemevoM ".ti
.setarc nedoow fo riap a otni sgniht sih gnikcap
stnemrag evaew-htnys eht fo ssenhtooms neklis eht dehcuot ohw enoyna tub
,dehcaorppa ehs sa pu dekool eH .tsacnwod seye
,srotsevni yna fo tnorf ni mrofrep ot ti teg t'ndluoC .os diarfA"
nepo xobloot eht gnivael
eninac naidanaC yffulf a
,noziroh tneve na otni detsiwt ytilaeR
"!detniaf s'ehs kniht I
.oihO regrem-erp larur ni gnisirprusnU
,nosrep ssenisub on m'I"
..." …eriw ,srevirdwercs
.srekoolno nailivic dna lanoisseforp fo elggag llams a dah
,gniht laer eht ekil dekool
.ekoms fo ffup ddo eht
?ni dekcik ylneddus tisnarT eht daH
sthgil deruoloc gnihsalf htiw noitpartnoc a gniyalpsid retto wollef a dna
.egassem rorre rehtonA
"?gid uoy ,looc s'tI
,detfihs sredrob stI
kcurt pukcip a fo bac eht dniheb deppils
,tnorf eht decarg sehctiws dna slaid lareveS
yas ot detnaw ehs sgniht eht fo lla kcab gnitiB ".esu
,ekil gnihtemos gnirettuM
,eye eht ni reh kool ot dewolla saw eh erusnu fi sa
…segassem rorre on
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
!pleh enoemoS !?ssiM
"…evah thgim sesuf eht fo eno kniht I
.enog saw xobloot ehT
.loof reporp a ekil nori gniredlos ym gnirb ot togrof I ekil skool dna
daeh sih koohs eh ,tnemom a retfA
,reilrae gnikrow t'nsaw ,mu tI"
.htaerb prahs a ni werd niraM
,mu ot ereh uoy era ,ih ,hU"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.etarc eht otni ti gnittup erofeb
,rae na dekcoc ehS
...eb t'ndluoc tI .langis oN
,won thgir detimil rehtar si egnar ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.egrahc gnidliub s'ecived eht ot
railimruF dna ,II neewolwoH gnimocpu eht gnidulcni
.stleb royevnoc gnirrihw dna sraeg gnikcalc lla
?ssiM ,thgirla uoy erA"
,srotcudnoc tneiciffe erom dna ylppus rewop retteb a htiw eveileb I tub
,htaerb sih rednu ,”esaelp ,krow“
.egamad yvaeh esuac ot gnihton ylerus tub ,ylivaeh ylriaf tinu siht gnisu neeb d'ehs ,seY !timmaD
.mrof dilos sti deniatniam wohemos hguoht
!egatoof siht evol dluow avalE forp tub
.noitisop lanigiro sti fo tfel eht ot hcni eno yletamixorppa kcirb eht dna
?eruliaf tnenopmoC
”noziroH tnevE“   yojne esaelP
.krow ti ekam ll'uoY"
,siseht reh rof dnoyeb dna evobA
.elddim eht ni deraeppa dah egassem rorre nA
.selif ngised s'tcetihcra nredom yna ni naht muesum a ni retteb tif dluow
!kcul nettor eht lla fO ”.langis oN“
,dehsinav elppir ehT
.xob latem eht fo edis eht no sregnif sih demmurd dna
!emit tsrif eht rof dlrow eht ot noitnevni sih dewohs eh yad eht saw sihT
slian s'haisoJ .eson reh delkcit enozo fo amora tniaf ehT
.hcum ekil kool t'ndid ti
.”lamron“ eb ot dray a rof dnal hguone gninwo redisnoc ot ,ddo woH
ereh nwohs gnieb snoitnevni eht fo ynaM
.epoh I ,ti no gnikrow peek ll'uoY
margorp seidutS mutnauQ s'USM fo stneduts weN
,epytotorp sih pu dekcip eH ".enihcam
.pot eht no seloh dellird hguorht dedurtorp
.sreilp fo riap a htaeneb dekcuT !erehT
,seigolohtna yrruf lareves ni dehsilbup krow dah sah eH
”erutuf eht fo emoh“ ,emorhc ehT
.enohpagem eht hguorht deniag eciov s'lammam rehto eht ssenllirhs eht etipsed
,oneR enacrA yb ”noziroH tnevE“
,spahrep neht
.gnihctiwt liat ,gnigammur nageb dna
elims ynit a ot nwod eelg dliw reh decrof niraM
selppir esoht gnirusne saw yek ehT
.yb dekcit tnemom A
,yalpsid elddim eht ni xof rednels eht ot dnim yna diap enoN
.noisserpmi gnitsal a gnitaerc deksir ti
lla ta selppir on ekam ot t'nsaw locotorp—
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.yad rehtona kcul ym yrt dna ni ti kcap llew sa thgiM"
,dil eht nepo gnisaE
.niaga eussi na gnivah eb tsum bal eht ta kcab maertspilS ehT
,gnirrihw detrossa eht evoba yltnetni gninetsil
klof ssenisub detius fo puorg ddo eht htiw ,seilimaf yltsom—elpoep fo stonk llams hguorht
.reh ta gnikool t'nsaw llits eh hguoht ,delims niraM ".niaga
?rorre eikoor emos edam ehs daH
!tsrif eht saw siht tub
.etrof reh neeb reven dah ognil doireP
"!yadot ,erutuf eht fo emoh eht ees dna edisni thgir petS"  oneR enacrA yb
.ti riaper ot em wollA .yrt rehtona..."
,talf yal srae siH
.stsep reted ot desoppus saw taht
.xif ysae na eb dluow siht ,ylikcuL
.drocer lluf ot smac reh dereggirt ydaerla dah niraM "!esaelp seY"
,tsap eht ni tcejbo egral ro nosrep a retla yllacisyhp t'ndluoc enO
,epahs ralucric dna foor lacinoc sti htiW
,hU" "?uoy pleh I yaM .niaga olleH"
,seirots mrof gnol dna trohs
desserD	         .mih erofeb elbat eht no xob latem gnimussanu eht fo tuo gnikop seriw fo elgnat a ta deirrow eh sa
"?…ssiM ,eman ruoy ksa I thgiM .sknaht ,hA"
.stisnarT evitucesnoc net ot pu rof detar eb ot desoppus erew esehT .trap paehC
.hguorht yawtrap deliaf reven stisnarT
.gnidrocer deppots ehs ,yldetaleB
.sraey eerht-ytnewt s'niraM fo tnemom tsedrah eht saw
egatoof erom pac dna yats ot detnaw ehs sa hcuM ".emit
.desae tsehc reh gnippirg sregnif ymmalc eht dna
".uoy htiw eerga dluow rotsevni na hsiw ylno I .esruoc fO" ".epoh
tnemegaruocne dna ygolopa tnelis gnihtaerb dna
.yltcerid mih ot ti nruter ot evah d'ehS !timmaD
.spih sih no sdnah
tcudorp gib txen eht rof sllats 'srotnevni gnisurep
,eht erutcip tsomla dluoc ehS
,yrtsudni yvaeh ro gnimraf ot detaler
.mih fo nees d'ehs spac eht fo tsom naht regnuoy hcum neve ,relkniV haisoJ
,selcihev tneicna eht neewteb deggel-ssorc gnipporD
srac fo wor a otni dekcud niraM
.gninettalf srae sih ,daeh sih koohs eH
.ytiniffaruF ro yrrufoS no
.ygolonhcet fo dnik siht rof seitilibissop gnizama fo sderdnuh era ereht ees nac uoy erus m'I tub
,ekops eh sa ezag sih deppord eH
,naelc saw noitcennoc eht tub ,krow
,reppoc tnrub fo tnecs tniaf a dniheb gnivael
htoob sih fo kcab eht ta dehsats xobloot llams a dah eh ,depoh d'ehs sA
,diuqil ot denrut yltpurba dah ti fi sa
tpecnoc eht psarg t'ndid netfo
edis nepo eht morf dellips gniriw fo ssem eht dna
,citsongaid deliated erom a pu thguorb egassem eht gnippaT
.gnikrep srae sih
.deneppah gnihtoN
,nori gniredlos enatub deworrob eht dna
.ecaf reh gnimraw taeh yb dewollof
,weksa ylthgils gnignah eit elprup a htiw
.sruoh eb dluoc hcihw
.rotacidni neerg a pu til taht hctiws a deppilf neht
”noziroH tnevE“ saw sihT
"?uoy wohs ,ha ,nac I ebyaM"
.ot desoppus s'ti ,rO"
gnivoM	         .emoh eht dna revaeb deodexut eht fo egami eht erots dluow smacteR reh os eciwt gniknilb
tcaer ot nageb selucelom sti sa kcirb eht dnuora remmihs tniaf eht pu kcip dluoc ehs ,scitpo decnahne eht htiW
,dehcaorppa ehs sa pu til seye siH
!flesmih lammam eht morf
,meht derongi yltsom ehS
desolc esac eht deppans ehs ,flesreh ot gniddoN
.emit gnorw eht ta srae gnorw eht ni detnalp
.ylesolc hctaw esaelP"
sledom rosseccus sti dna ti nees d'ehS
.tfel d'ehs nehw ta gnikool neeb d'ehs nades neerg emas eht otni devloser dnA...
saedi dna sdrow yb enod eb dluoc egamad fo ytnelp tub
,ti fo emoc dluow gnihtoN
erow ehs esuolb yelsiap dna s'iveL ehT
.sloot elbatius tub ,detacitsihposnu
.sruoh yduts gnol tnecer reh htiw nevE !diputS
.nori gniredlos sih nruter llew sa thgiM
.htoob eht delcric niraM
.nwod flesreh gnittap ,denworf ehS
.selur eht gnikaerb eb dluow taht
gnikahs s'dnah reh morf daer ot drah saw yalpsid ehT
.emit emos ti evig tsuJ"
sllats eht fo htoB
,ti dexif yeht litnu tiaw ot evah d'ehS
;tcejbus yna htiw noitcaretni fo setunim wef a naht erom oN
,slaid eht fo eno detsujda
.yap esoht tsael tA
.dworc gnilgnim eht fo stohs lareneg gnippac ylno
."llaceR" desserp ehS ".haisoJ ,eyB"
,siad a pota gnidnats revaeb yltrop eht tsap deklaw ehs sa elims a dih niraM
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT morf secapS
,xobloot sih erofeb doots haisoJ
eussi ytisrevinu reh fo rednilyc emorhc keels eht werd ehs
.ainrofilaC morf m'I ,yrroS"
trihs etihw desserp a ni
.dehcrul ylleb reH
,yawyna ti deppac ehS
?siseht reh eltit ehs thgim tahW
,tca eht ni reh hctac dluoc haisoJ erofeb yawa detrad dna loot eht dehctans ehS
,edistuo eht nO "?od ti seod tahW"
.stneve tceffa t'ndid
,flesreh gnileetS
eson sih pu sessalg sih degdun ohw
"?uoy era ,gnivael ton er'uoY"
!tey detpoda neeb t'ndah esarhp tahT .timmaD "?yvoorG"
!retal yrots a fo kceh a ekam dluow sihT
.lluks sih ot dennip deniamer srae sih tub ,deggurhs haisoJ
.tisnarT fo hcrul dlim eht rof gnicarb yllatnem
...hguoht gnillaf ekil leef yllausu t'ndid tI
.elzzum sih revo dehctiwt elims tniaf a dna
!dluow tlas sih htrow rotnevni yna—
.kcirb a gnicudorp erofeb tnemom a elbat eht htaeneb degammur xof eht
.htoob s'haisoJ drawot kcab degdurt ehs ,teef reh ot gnilbboW
,lio fo gnat reivaeh eht htiw dedlem ssarg demmirt yltnecer fo tnecs naelc eht ,shtoob eht gnomA
.haisoJ ta pu kcab decnalg ehs sa
tirpluc eht saw erehT
evah dluohs are siht fo serots scinortcelE
...loot-itlum reh htiw xif kciuq a
,htrof dna kcab gnikool
gnikatsim on saw ereht
.denediw seye s'niraM ".yad
.redluohs reh revo dellac ehs "!kcul dooG"
,nwod kaerb yletaidemmi t'nseod ti erehw eno yllaicepse dna ,elacs regral a no noitartsnomed a edivorp dluoc uoy fI"
.ecnatsid reh tpek niraM—
,shtoob eht dniheb ylkciuq gnivoM …tcaf nI
.ekoms fo lruc niht a gniliart roticapac a—
.gnihtemos otno er'uoy kniht I tub
.noitseuq on ,yrotcafsitas ti dnif dluow lenap weiver ehT
.lodi daed-gnol reh ot
,dias haisoJ ",sgniht sevom …tI"
tekcop reh morf nocaeB ketrelkniV
.noitasrevnoc eht tuo denut niraM tub ,noitnevni sih gnidnefed
,raelc saw gnikcart ehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.esion dworc dna ,gnirettalc
,enola doots haisoJ
.elbat eht no nrettap otaccats a deppat
,enips reh nwod deppird dloc ycI
,noci "llaceR" gniknilb eht deppat ehS
.yalpsid eht detcepsni ehs ,gninworF
,delppir kcirb eht ,nehT
.taorht reh morf dellor lworg A
,semit ynam tisnarT eht nees d'ehS
,lesaew eht dna regit eht neewteb deppils ehS
,seye gnihctaw rof tuoba gnicnalG
.htoob s'haisoJ ta ytivitca eht yb deugirtni
.yalpsid eht pu dellup dna
.nocaeB eht detfil ehs sa
.delwarc niks s'niraM
.lla retfa thgir saw dad ym ebyaM"
,remmah a :kcots koot ehs
.dednuow ylsuoveirg neeb dah gniht eht fi sa
.noisiv reh dellif ylraen kcirb eht litnu
sebut ssalg fo riap A
,shtoob eht raen ssarg eht no dekrap
,tey eman reporp a fo thguoht t'nevah I .dalg m'I"
shtoob fo swor eht fo eno dniheb tops teiuq A
.elims ediw a mih dehsalf ehS
,noitartsnomed epytotorp tsrif a teg ot tuoba saw ehS
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.dnah sih fo kcab eht dettap ehs ,tuo gnihcaeR
.elbissopmi saw taht—
.ti gnikatsim on saw ereht ,renwo sti ekiL
,rellitotor devorpmi na ffo gniwohs okceg eht fo noitpecxe eht htiW
,ti dnuora pool eriw eht decalp dna
…bal eht ni ti nettogrof evah ylbissop t'ndluoc ehS ?ti saw erehW
.nori gniredlos a saw dedeen ehs llA
.xob eht fo pot eht gnippat
.dekrep srae siH "!hA"
!eman reh evoba ”scimanyD mutnauQ fo retsaM“
.sretemarap elbatpecca nihtiw—
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.elbissopmi eb dluow ti ediseb ro pota gnidliub
.stxet reh fo ynam ni
.enihcam daed a htiw dnuora gnikcits esnes oN
.swodniw sti hguorht kcab decnalg dna
nocaeB reh tuo dellup ehs
!meht wohs tsuj ,skrow tI
ecived s'haisoJ morf ecnerefretni ronim dewohs tuodaer gnikcart ehT
cif ceps fo yteirav ediw a setirw ohw
.deworruf worb s'niraM "…sey
.kcart dluoc seye reh neve naht retsaf decalpsid
ecived eht ot txen ti tes eH
.pool eriw a ot detcennoc kcab eht morf sgnorp latem owT
.evael t'ndluoc eH
... …raf os tey raen os
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.gninnips saw dlrow ehT ".yap
.evael ot gninrut ydaerla saw ehS
.elzzum sih nwod gnippils sessalg ,detloj eH ".krow