.rotaderp a er’uoY
”?uoy no pord eht tog enoemoS ?stopS ,niaga yaS“
ot koot ti gnol woh uoy dnimer thgim I
,navinim ylimaf a dna sub a neewteb derednuht rac ehT ”—rac taht dliub
,rebif nobrac dna emorhc ni elcycrotom lufrewop a was reteP ”.yppah dna taf
.tnatnuocca na saw ynohtnA
kcab xob taht teg t'ndid eh fi tuB .ytiradilos dna
taoc sih fo gninil eht ni neddih tekcop eht rof deporg sregnif gnikahs siH
.nmad ,nmad ,nmaD .ytpme—
.tekcop s’latsyrC fo tuo kcab dekans wap s’reteP
.hsad eht no nottub a deppat eH ”.eybdoog yas ot
,tnorferots derettahs eht revo derebmalc eH
.dekcarc saw ecaf hctaw siH
,nrut eht dnuora deppihw eh sa gnicnuob saw liat sih timda t'ndid eh fi gniyl eb d’eH
.latsyrC .esruoc fO
”topS eht skraM xE“ saw sihT
”.ti ekam reven ll'uoy ,stopS .ho—
.mih erofeb etalpecaf knalb eht otni dekool reteP
.meht neewteb noitcesretni eht ssorca detrats kcurt imes A
raeg otni rac eht demmals reteP
,yobdooG ydduB yb
.keehc sih otni worruf peed a gniggid dna niks eht gnittilps
)reetyksuH yb daer(
.daeha tegrat eht s'taht ,reteP ,demrifnoC“ ”.meht dnuoF“
.esolc os erew I dna uoY“
.rehtie t'nevah I“
.imes eht rednu demmar tI
wap s’ynohtnA ni xob a tup eH
,eceip eno ni eriter ot dnetni I
ni dereggats doolb ni dehcnerd tekcaj rennid etihw deppir a ni hateehc a ,tnorf eht tA
.dloc deppots hateehc ehT
!deppots saw tegrat eht—
.ytiniffAruF dna yrruFoS no tra dna seirots stsop ohw
hctawtrams sih deppat eH
tcepser fo ngis a sa ecaf sih otno dils nirg yhtoot a dna
.yldaed saw elims reH
,thgiR“ ”?thgir ro tfeL“
,detceje taes regnessap ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.gnorw saw I .did I thguoht I“
,tnilg latem a saw erehT
.won margorp eht pu gnilluP .esruoc fO“
.rood eht gnurps dna rac sih ot revo deggoj eH
.degrahc rac ehT
.daeha raor enigne eht tel dna
.resolc ecaf sih dellup ehS
,hteet gnissim t'nsaw eH
.temleh eht ffo tfil ot
.mih gnissik fo trohs deppots ehS
.sneris fo dnuos eht ot ekowa reteP ,retal stnemoM
.og dluow ti sa kcab raf sa taes sih denael dna
temleh elcycrotom a dna
.eb dluohs eye thgir a erehw denetsilg enots eulb dloc A
?rof siht fo tser eht saw tahw ,llew—
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
reisae hcum ti sekam taht dnA“ .ti dah eH
,lla rof eno :reetyksuH yb
.ynohtnA erofeb doots yltnelis reteP
,tnaruatser eht edisnI
.emac ti yaw eht kcab delbma dna
,dnuora gnuws dna mih was tsilcycrotom ehT
.hcamots eht ni dekcehc-redluohs gnitteg erofeb
.era uoy llams woh
,llaf dna esir tsehc s’reteP dehctaw erugif ehT
”.sruo eb dluoc dlrow ehT
.erehwyreve tuo gnikcits ssalG
,retsloh redluohs sih morf nug s’reteP koot tI
.tnaliassa nwonknu na yb tuo dekconk tsuj saw I !deR“
.ffo deps dah tsilcycrotom a dewohs daor eht no kcart erit A
”.camuD .rM ,rehtegot emit ruo nettogrof ev’I kniht t'noD“
.pu flesmih dellup reteP
.ffo erot foor eht sa deliathsif tI
.os kniht t'nod I“ ”.sdne dlrow ehT“
”?retfa er'uoy ohw aedi ynA
,htob ni smaercs dna spsag gnisuac
.siht ekil stnaruatser ot tnew reven eH
.denekcalb eb dluow seye sih htoB
”.thgil eht ta tfeL“ ”?yaw hcihW .enoN“
rehtael kcalb fo espmilg a thguac dna
.mih ot txen taes eht otni deppord tsilcycrotom eht sa dekaerc rehtaeL
.no dewolp rac eht tub ,latem fo hsarc suorednuht a ni delpmurc foor ehT
,redir railimaf a htiw
.flesmih ot yltfos delworg reteP
.drawrof  derednuht dna
”.erew htob ew llams woH
.enog saw attereB siH
.pu dleh teg t'ntsuM
* * * .ffo deldnurt dna
.siht naht retteb gnihton s'erehT“ .tuo deirc eH
…daer ot ikahK rof ysae s’ti os stnedni on htiw lairA stp61 si siht dna ,thgin ymrots dna krad a saw tI   .eenk eno ot deppord dna
.epahs dab ni saw tius siH
.rood tnorf eht ta gnissuf sd ertiam ees dluoc ynohtnA
.tuons sih morf gnideelb saw eh tub
”.stopS ,cainam a ekil evird uoY“
xE“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
”?kcab ti teg t'nod uoy fi sneppah tahW“ ”.xob taht tnaw I“
?…reteP .depsag ynohtnA
.drawno mih gnirad
reh etsat tsomla dluoc eH ”.em devol uoY
tekcop tekcaj sti otni xob llams eht deffuts neht
.noitcafsitas htiw derrup mih no erugif ehT
raeg otni rac eht detfihs reteP
”?ti kcart uoy naC
reteP ffo nug eht dellup tsilcyc ehT
.klawedis eht no dednal eh sa ssalg gnihcnurc
.thgilnoom eht ni deremmihs ruf etihw-dnomaid reH
.eno rof lla dna ,lla rof eno
.xob eht deggat I
eltsirb liat sih tlef camuD reteP
”.tsal ew sa gnol sa rof ,dlrow eht dnuora em esahc oT .em tnaw uoY
uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.senal dedworc neewteb gnivaew
.leehw gnireets eht otni dehsams eH
.htuom sih ni doolb eht revo
,ecaf sih dehctarcs ylwols dna delworg ehS ”.seY“ ”.ti naem uoY“
.emarfrood eht fo tfel saw tahw revo doolb fo lufhtuom a tips reteP
—tub ,ereht erew syek dna tellaW
.doolb fo llems yvaeh eht hguorht tnecs rieht ezingocer t'ndluoc reteP
.rotarelecca eht no deppets dna denworf eH
eb ot demees kcurt wot A
.nwod flesmih dettap reteP
…dezilaer reven I—
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.laid deeps tsrif eht tih dna
.xob tpircsednon elttil a devomer dna
.hctawtrams s’reteP morf tehtipe desserpmoc a dna
eht yldrah s’woN“
”topS eht skraM
”.sracs evah llits I
enal txen eht otni demmals reteP ”.luferac eB
.tekcaj tius s’reteP hguorht delfir wap devolg A
.syobsub fo gnorht a tsap deredluohs dna
.traeh sih ta detniop saw attereB lekcin-dna-tunlaw nwo sih dna
”topS eht skraM
.drah dnuorg eht tih eH
enigne eht dennug reteP
.yrrauq sih no ni desolc eh sa gnicar saw traeh sih dna
.uoy htiw ereht tuo ton m’I dalg m’I—“
.ria eht otni latsyrC gnitekcor
dnuora delrihw eH
”?kcab yaw eht lla dlof rac siht ni staes eht ,deR“
.skcolb owt thgiarts neht
,srotsecna sih deifsitas esahc ehT
.lausunu demees tI
.rac strops a flah yawa gniluah
.liat a gnitcepxe t'nsaw I“
yobdooG ydduB yb
”.xob eht dna nug ym htiw ffo edam yehT
,yobdooG ydduB yb
tekcaj sih otni nwes tekcop neddih eht dnuof neht
wenk I naht reggib hcum os s'dlrow ehT“
.temleh eht fo tuo srae reh dellup dna daeh reh koohs tibbar ehT
:reetyksuH yb uoy rof daer
xE“   yojne esaelP  .eno rof lla dna
.ti peek em tel ot tnaw uoy taht kniht I
.tsilcycrotom eht fo trohs tsuj deddiks dna sekarb eht demmals eH
.yaw ruoy gnimoc sresiurc elpitlum swohs dnab ecilop—gnivom teG
ereht thgir saw tegrat ehT
.rettahs wodniw tnorferots eht draeh eh erofeb tsomla