llaw dloc eht tsniaga depmuls eH
”…yrros os m’I …iatnoS“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.mih gnirusaem ,ogaL ot esolc ylbatrofmocnu deppots ehS .reppoc dna enob htiw dialni ylenif
edis eno no depmats saw ierG sud novU rorepmE fo ecaf ehT
”.ti tuoba wonk esle enoyna tel t’now-w I tub ,mih dnif ll’I woh-h wonk t’nod I .nosdnarg ruoy ot ti evig lliw I“
.elttob ynit a morf deppird eh tnevlos gnillems-prahs a fo spord wef a htiw ti dexim tnemtrapmoc ytpme na ni dna—
.htaerb fo tuo gnispalloc flesmih dnuof eh dna
”—I …uoy rof erom od t’ndluoc I yrros m’I .lliw I
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
:htab elbissop tsekciuq eht eb dluow siht dediced eh ,loop eht otni teef nworb sih gniknis retfA
,kcohs eht morf derevocer ydob sih ecnO .gniknilbnu
.memlamlaW .efas peek
.namow daed eht dlot eh ”,siht ekil uoy evael t’nac I“
.mih fo tnorf ni gab rehtael sih gnihsup ,ni delwarc neht
.worram sih fo tuo thgiarts taeh eht dekcus syawla evaC dnomaiD ehT
.semeht cihpromoporhtna aiv ,noitamrofsnart dna ,redneg
.maertsnwod esahc rieht deunitnoc dna detcaer yltfiws dauqs reH
.mih drawot yltcerid gninnur saw xof yarg a
,taebtraeh a detsal dah ti fi erus t’nsaw eh taht esnetni os neeb dah ecneirepxe ehT
”,od ot tahw wonk t’nod I“
,doowladnas der fo wobssorc lufituaeb a htiw gnola reviuq a saw kcab reh ta gnignaH
,lleftseH raen flesruoy dnif reve uoy fi“—
;dnah sih nepo ot derad yllanif ogaL
,teef sih ot delbmuts ogaL
:mih dnuora gnihtyreve fo hsiugna eht leef dluoc eh fi sa saw tI
.niaga keerc eht yb derehtag sreidlos dna sdnuoh eht lla was dna nibac eht fo egde eht dnuora dekeep eH
.daed saw iatnoS
.esion tsethgils eht ton edam hcihw
,drawrof eno rehto eht desiar dna kcab sih dniheb dnah deidoolb sih tpek ogaL
”?eman ruoy s’tahW
,reilrae mih dniheb rood eht desolc dah eh dezilaer ylneddus eH
.kcahs eht fo tnorf eht ot kcab delbmuts neht
.dloc gninnur si liart ruo ,ogaL“
,ekih eht ,loohcs ta thgif eht—
,keerc eht drawot deklaw dna yawa denrut anrojF
.yob ,tiurcer taerg a ekam d’uoY
.kcab sih dniheb spitregnif derevoc-doolb sih gnilaecnoc ,deremmats ogaL
,niwdlaB níuqaoJ yb
sllaw on ot txen rood gnidnatseerf eht dnuora deklaw eH
,ksam eht ta derats eh
.lirep reh dootsrednu eh wenk ehs fi sa ,ogaL ta pu dekool neht
.esaelp ,nosdnarg ym rof evig ylnO
”—ot deen I …I .gnideelb era uoy ,pleh deen uoy tuB
”—ot uoy ekat nac I ?nosdnarg ruoy si erehW“ ”.terceS
.dnif tel ton ,esaelP“
;aialA dnuora dekan gnieb elbatrofmocnu leef ton did ogaL
,dnah gnorts a htiw mlap sih gnirevoc namow eht tlef eH
,slwoh eht fo noitcerid eht ni htap elbbep eht pu gnikool ,rood gnidnatseerf s’kcahs eht yb doots eH
.wohyna ssenisub s’ydobon saw ti dna
,redluob ynnus eht ffo sehtolc mraw yllufrednow sih deleep ,tuo kcab delwarc eH
.leets dehsurb fo roloc eht erew seye reH
.meht ni setsap deird ,lufroloc htiw stnemtrapmoc erauqs fo seires a delaever denepo nehw taht
.seye sih ot dilos gnimoceb ylwols mrof regral hcum a tub
.selbbep deidoolb eht fo tnecs eht pu dekcip ylisae sdnuoh eht ,keerc eht tA
?mih emalb dluoc ohw dna
ot keerc ybraen eht esu osla
;detatiseh ylfeirb dna seloheye eht hguorht dekool eH .gnirulla
.efas ti peek d’I uoy desimorp I“
:gab rehtael sih morf hcnul loohcs sih dellup neht
aingisni gniknar a htiw deoottat dna devahs saw elpmet tfel reh
,oga sega ekil demees sraey owT .decsinimer ogaL
.nirg gnidaelp ,elbatnemal taht dloh ot
”.esaelp ,sdnah ruoy em wohs tsuJ“ ”—I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
.yltnetni erom netsil ot daeh sih denrut neht
,ti ta dekool ylurt
;emit tsrif eht rof ,delims anrojF ”.lliw I
,slruc yddum sih fo erac laiceps gnikat ,etsah ni dehsaw eH
.liart a fo hcraes ni ti dessorc tser eht elihw ,maertsnwod keerc eht dewollof eerht
,sarreiS mirgliP eht fo edis siht no sexof yarg evah t’nod ew ,xof yarg a saw ehS“
.tpew ylnepo dna
.soottat ni derevoc saw niks deroloc-attocarret reh
.ereht llits ylbainednu
,noitsuahxe dna raef ni gnikahs ,reh dniheb dekcehc xof ehT
.elzzum wolloh eht ,seloheye gnicreip eht ,srae detniop eht gnileef
.gnitaeb a etiuq ogaL evag eh ,sdnah sih was rehtaf sih nehw
”?ti si tahW“ ”.efas peek
,deilper ehs ”,iatnoS“
.redluohs sih revo gab eht gnuls dna eson sih ffo tons eht depiw eH
,taht did elpoep nehw ti detah eh—
.taht od ot woh mih thguat dah aialA
,deliaw ehs ,seye etarepsed ,dezarc htiW
.dedaehthgil gnileef
”.ylraelc rebmemer dna drah knihT .sliated yna piks ton oD
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
.seciverc sih lla yrd ezeerb eht tel ot daerps dna pu skeehc ttub
,uoy tnes oraD anrojF meht lleT
.ezeerb nmutuA-dim eht thgif ot hguone eb ton dluow hkonnuS fo thgil gnitib eht neve dna
,redluohs s’namow dlo eht no gnihsup deirt llits tub
.wobssorc lufituaeb reh drawrof dellup neht ,dias ehs
,niwdlaB níuqaoJ yb
.tsehc sih fo tuo taeb ot tuoba saw traeh s’ogaL
.edilloc ot tuoba era seirots owt ehT
.evac eht ot kcab dehsur neht ,derebmemer eh !iatnoS …fo tiusrup ni yaw gnol a delevart ev’tsum anrojF .raf
,loohcs ta thgif a otni nettog dah ogaL gnuoy ,emit tsaL
.yawyna od ot krow emos dah eh dna
,ydob daed eht ta gnikool dediova eH
,niwdlaB níuqaoJ yb
,iatnoS ro ,flesmih dlot eh
:elpmet tfel ,devahs reh no soottat gniknar eht ees ylraelc ogaL gnittel ,sgnidnuorrus reh dekcehc namow ehT
,dehcated ksam eht litnu daeh sih gnihctarcs
:dekan yletelpmoc saw tub sserd ecal a gniraew t’nsaw ehs taht won was ogaL
,edih uoy ,suoregnaD
,lejurK revlis A
,ksam xof a saw was eh tahW
.hcuop rehtael a tuo dellup eh ,yawa hsart eht gnikcut retfA
.smug dna hteet deidoolb htiw mih ta delims ehS
aipotooZ ekil smlif ni
,yaw rehtie ti rof llams oot saw daeh s’ogaL—ecaf s’enoemos ot hcatta dluohs ti woh raelc ton saw ti os
.s’ogaL tem seye yarg ,dloc reh os nwod dettauqs ehS
,ti htiw eno gnimoceb
.efil sih fo noitrop laitnatsbus a ot detnuoma sraey owT
,ecaf sih otno desuf ksam eht fi sa tlef eH
,erom ecno dias eh ”,yrros os m’I“
,gniyd iatnoS fo niap eht
:ekatsim evarg eno deciton eh nehw flesmih gnisopmoc saw ogaL
.eloh eht fo tuo flesmih gniggid ,deilper ylkciuq ogaL ”,ezis rieht yb syob eht morf slrig eht llet nac uoY“
”!keerc eht drawot nar xof ehT“
.elims suoutsepmet dna elbadimrof a
,tekcub delddir-eloh a no ssa demraw ylluf sih tas eH
,maertsnwod dessip eh ,yrd ecnO
,eripmE naigeN eht morf
.sdnuow dna sehtolc sih hsaw
,dluoc eh sa llew sa sehtolc sih dehsaw ogaL
.yawrood terces eht ot deirruh dna tuo deirc eh
.efas ti peek ll’I ,esimorp I“
.pu flesmih dellup ogaL nehw retal ruoh na neeb evah tsum tI
.revo yaw reh no doolb fo spird gnivael
.yrd ot reuqcal gnilkraps eht rof gnitiaw ,slian sih no welb eH
,kcalb ylinnacnu ,dezilyts ylivaeh saw tI
,gnitivni tlef ytivacnoc eht tub
.gniwols ron mih gninoitseuq tuohtiw ot detniop ogaL noitcerid eht ni denrut sreidlos ehT
.yks yrrats tsepeed eht ekil
dna yad eht ssap dluoc eh
,thgil ylbissopmi saw ti—
.stcnitsni sih htiw hguorht wollof ot egru na tlef eh tub ,tnatropmi saw tnemom siht yhw erus t’nsaw eH
.yad eritne na ro
.dnop dnuor eht ni slarips yreif werd sevael nellaf eht nehw
,yaw taht reitterp dekool eH .did tsuj eh
;gnippird saw kcen reh fo kcab ehT
.ylper elpmis reh saw ”…vlisgrangA“ .evac eht fo diov eht ni ees ot krad oot saw mih ot gnidnah saw ehs revetahW .deriuqni eh
,mih fo tnorf ni teef evif erem a detlah xof yarg ehT ?doolb taht sI
.nibac eht fo kcab eht drawot maeb delppot a ssorca deppoh dna
,efas vlisgrangA
.seye sih ni pu dellew sraeT
I“ ”…g …ai …kaaB !gaikaaB !vlapma tafelehk htilaab ,vliS
,thgis fo tuo erew sreidlos eht ecnO
,lufituaeb saw ksam ehT
etirovaf sih ,eno eulb eht—
.sdnuoh fo kcap a dna sreidlos gnieelf saw ohw
.rethguad fo nos ,iemnoB“
,keerc eht drawot delbma dna niaga tuo delwarc eh ,daetsnI
.retemirep s’kcahs eht denroda taht selbbep eht revo der gnippird
.edirts tnanimod ,lufrewop a htiw
.nioc revlis dedis-neetxis a saw ti ni
,raey fo emit siht devol eH
,ysub saw aialA nehw nwo sih no emac semitemos eh
.ycavirp latot ni nehw slian sih detniap ylno eh ,syadawoN
…ti saW …xof eht did erehW .ogaL m’I …I“
.mih drawot yltcerid gnimoc
.tnemrot gnihca ni edolpxe niarb sih gnikam
.deilppa eb ot ydaer reuqcal lianregnif fo tnuoma thgir eht tsuj dah noos dna noitulos eht derrits eh hsurb etunim a htiW
;slian sih tniap ot dekil eh yhw wonk t’ndid ogaL ”.seittit
.dnuorg eht no doolb deird-kcalb eht fo espmilg a thguac llits tub
,rruL ,esle gnihtyna wonk t’nod I“
os s’tahT .thguoht ogaL
”?pleh deen uoy oD“
.erom ecno seye sih ni sraet gnidnif
:loohcs ta reilrae pu netaeb mih nettog dah tahw saw sihT
,ereht llits saw tI
.nibac eht fo sdraob deretnilps eht revo doolb fo liart a saw ereht
kaeps ,hsimacsiM“
gnirtsward wenis eht desserac ehs—
,tuo deirruh eH ”!esaelp ,teiuq yatS !esimorp I ,seY“
.tnatropmi dekool ehS
”elavrehtiW fo floW“
.ssenkrad etelpmoc ni iatnoS gnivael
.esolc pu sliated eht denimaxe dna doolb eht ffo dehsaw eh erehw
.maerts eht otni dehsaw eb ot llef taht fael egnaro yreve ni llec yreve fo
ylregae lla ti deruoved yob ehT
,dloc oot yaw saw retawtlem laicalg eht
,rehtael tsenif eht fo tius niht a erow ehS
xof dednuow a tuoba
.erofeb nosrep daed a nees reven dah ogaL
.gnireviuq spil ,delbmum eh
.evaC dnomaiD eht otni dekan dedaeh neht ,ffo ti koohs
,gninetsilg dna tew saw tI
,htap eht dnuora denrut tsuj dah sdnuohxof fo kcap ehT
.kcahs eht ta devirra eh nehw god a ekil gnitnap saw eH
.erus t’nsaw eh ;god fo tros emos ro ,ksam flow a ebyam ro
.tcatnoc eye gnisol tuohtiw lla
…dnatsrednu t’nod I-
,yllufniap dewollaws eH
.reh ot kcab tcejbo krad eht dednah eH
,ti gnipleh on saw ereht wenk eH .eid oT .enolA
,kcab derats seloheye sti fo sdiov eht dna
,secnereffid lacimotana tuoba seitisoiruc rieht deifsitas oga gnol dah yeht
:tuo daerps ot delangis redael ednolb riehT
.gnilwoh tnatsid a draeh eh ,kcahs eht ot kcab deklaw eh sA .desserd tog dna
.rallec ymoolg eht ni dekan gnittis ,dloc gnitteg saw eH
tuoedih terces sih ot og ot dediced d’eh ,tuo gnidnif rehtaf sih fo lufraef dna
,erofeb ereht xof a neeb dah ereht woh dneherpmoc ot elbanu llits
,htmraw gnitaidar redluob tilnus a revo talf dna tew meht deppolp
,enips dna lluks sih otni nwod dehcnurc dna
,thguoht eh ?sevloW
,gab sih ni dekeep dah setamssalc sih
.tuo detrulb eh ”!ereht revO“
.swob evrucer dna swobssorc gnidloh osla elihw sehsael rieht dleh sreidlos eviF
.ynoga elbabircsedni saw neht decneirepxe eh tahW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ylleb dna sedalb redluohs reh morf delb dna ,derepmihw
;puorg eht del riah ednolb-revlis ,gnol htiw namow llat A
.eciov tew-gnilgrug ,ypsar a ni meht gnikaeps ,sdrow eht dnif ot delggurts ehS ”…nommoC elttil
.liat eht no epirts kcalb ,kcab yarg ,swap maerC
”.ni llef tub keerc eht pmuj ot deirt ehS .tuoba gniffins era sgod ruoy erehw“—
.lufetarG .htinnu ,ogaL
.tnatropmi dekool yehT
”.srehto ot terceS
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
:ti did eh emit tsrif eht elbuort gib ni nettog dah eH
”.detcepsus I sa si ti tub ,etanutrofnu si tahT .ogaL ,uoy knahT“
.deriuqni namow eht ”?ehS“
”—ll’I ,pleh teg og ll’I
.retfa lenap nedoow eht dna tsrif rood dnuor eht gnisolc
,vlapma ,vlisgrangA“
xob nedoow etaciled a devomer dna sgnirtsward eht denesool eH
.edisni og t’ndid ogaL
.ecnerever dekovni dna rewop deduxe ti ;ereves
.seert eht pu neve dna daor eht gninnacs ,dehcaorppa ylmlac redael ednolb riehT
.slianregnif dereuqcal sih rof ,sdnah sih no doolb eht rof :elbuod saw rorret s’ogaL ”.sdnah ruoy ees em tel woN“
.depsag ehs ”!yatS !oN !tserG“
.iemnoB rof ylno evig
ehk htamle htaë nneiJ“
.esimorp ,esaelP .iemnoB
”.eripmE eht rof gnithgif ffo retteb eb d’uoY
.ylleb eht no rehtona dna—
,traeh sih ni niap eht
.rae reh dniheb yaw eht lla nar yeht taht suoremun os erew yeht
,detuops ylsuovren dna taorht sih ni pmul eht dewollaws ogaL ”.rruL ,seY“
,thguoht eh ,deneppah tsuj tahw dnatsrednu t’nod I .dlrow eht ro
nihc sih htiw detniop eh—”yaw taht revo tneW .truh yldab demeeS
,ytilauxes fo semeht no gnihcuot
.srellewd evac cirabrab eb ot gnidneterp ,evaC dnomaiD rieht edisni dehtolcnu rehtegot emit dneps netfo dluow dna ,od nerdlihc sa
.slian sih edih ot pu mlap
,thgis fo tuo saw anrojF ecnO
”,pleh ruoy rof uoy knahT .ogaL ,tnavresbo yrev era uoY“
:sgniht fo tsegnarts eht was eh ereht dna
.detnemal ehs ”!esimorP“
,smrof dednuopmoc debircsed secafrus tseinit eht nevE
erehw—nibac tcilered a dniheb redluob a no devrac rallec tneicna na—
.thguoht ogaL ,eripmE naigeN eht morf gnikram era esohT
,kcor toh a no delwarps eH
slruc s’ogaL delffur ehs ,doots ehs sA
.ti pots ot elbanu ,lla ti tlef eH
,deppans ehs ”!efaS“
”redlo era uoy nehW“
.faelesrom ni depparw yttap ecir a dna raep a
,semit fo tseb eht erew esohT  2 fo 2 traP
,lenap terces eht nepo gnuws eh
.eman nwo ruoy noitnem dna
.eman reh gnirepsihw
,keerc eht ni skcor rednu gnidih hsifyarc ynit eht fo
.tsehc sih ot tcejbo kcalb ,egral a desserp dna ogaL drawot dehcaer ehS
w I“ ”.efas peek ,esaelP …vlisgrangA
tcejbo eht koot dna yawa mra reh devom ylluftcepser eH
.namow dlo delknirw a yal ti no dna
”!ylkciuq ,uoy edih ll’I ,ereh revO“
.gnimaercs saw eh taht erawa ton saw ogaL
,ydob dekan sih fo suoicsnoc-fles yrev gnieb etipseD
.ffo sehtolc deiddum sih koot eh erehw
,tcafitra desruc eht pu dekcip ylluferac
.yerp ysae dellems dna ,sreuqcal lianregnif fo xob sih dnuof
.was uoy tahw yltcaxe em llet ot uoy deen I
.dezilaer eh ,selbbep eht no doolb s’ereht ,tihS
.sruoh rof meht hctaw dluoc eh—
.ekat uoy ,vlisgrangA“ .stsaerb dekni ,gniggas reh revo dnah a htiw
daD regdaB yldduC eht ,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
”.kcab eb ll’I ,yatS
morf tprecxe na fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT      .tfel neht
,noitcivnoc elbacilpxeni na htiw ,neht tub
,tserof eht fo niap eht
”elavrehtiW fo floW“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.seittit taf ruoy ssik ot sekil neliaW dneirfyob ruoy teb I .sirroB ,yssis eht era uoY“ .derettum-flah
,ekil ,kcab eht no tuc a dah ehS
,nneij htinnu ssoV“
.uoy dnif meht tel t’now-
,eloh eht revo lenap degnih eht desolc ylitsah ogaL
,ybraen dekrul seips esac ni ylluftsurtsid dnuora gnikeep retfA
.sdnuoh era esoht ,oN
,lios eht ni smrowhtrae eht fo
,dnuorg eht no deliaw eH
.thgil eht fo elgna eht no gnidneped gnignahc
.ti otno devrac sliated etacirtni tsom eht htiw
.evaC dnomaiD eht drawot detlob dna htaerb peed a koot ogaL
,ti revo lla gnippird thgilnus fo selkraps htiw kcalb erup
.eman a tegrof reven I
.duht delffum a htiw deppord gab ehT
.resolc dednuos sdnuoh eht fo gnilwoh ehT
.gniniart reporp teg uoy erus ekam ll’I
.keerc eht drawot meht delruh dna selbbep detniat eht lla debbarg eh ,ti tuoba hcum oot gnikniht tuohtiW
,erom ecno iatnoS ta dekool ogaL
.erusaelpsid sih edih ot deganam eh depoh dna
.raef htiw etihw tnew seye reh neht dnA ”…lufetarG
.desufnoc ,deppots neht
etsap fo tib a ffo deparcs eH
.htuom reh morf gnilgnad elttips der
.ecaf sih ot ksam eht desserp eh
yensiD ta krow sih rof nwonk
.ti ni dnah thgir sih raems ot deganam ylno tub ffo doolb eht epiw ot deirt eH
.tsehc reh ot gnihtemos gnidloh ylevitcetorp elihw seenk reh ot pu flesreh dehsup namow dlo ehT ”—did erehW
,trid eht no talf keehC
”elavrehtiW fo floW“   yojne esaelP
,yltnedifnoc dehcaorppa reidlos ehT
.namow dlo na fo esproc eht saw deniamer taht lla won dna
.gab sih edisni ksam eht dih dna ,evac eht ot kcab tnew
.rehto eht no ligis naigeN eht fo slerual eht dna
.seergilif cihpargillac ,etarobale ni kcab egrem ot sfitom dettonk ni tilps tub
,agaS ssoN eht ,seires ysatnaf nwo sih gnitirw yltnerruc dna
.detaesuan mih edam doolb fo llems yvaeh-nori ,yttun ehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.suonevar mih tfel lla dah retaw dloc eht
.dlog fo snoitalletsnoc ekil kcuts hcihw ,slian sih revo acim fo skcelf ynit delknirps dna dehsurc ogaL ,pu deird reuqcal eulb eht erofeB
.slangis dnah gnivaw
.ereh yats ,iatnoS“ .ybraen deohce sdnuoh eht fo gnilwoh eht sa ,derepmihw ehs ”!edih ,efaS“
?xof eht-ht si erehW“
.seirotciv dna sronoh suoiverp fo ecnedive—
,detrats ogaL ”—teg uoy did woH“
,eno otni segami elpitlum gnivaew
,delbmert xof ehT
,doolb fo loop a saw dnuorg dloc eht nO
,resolc dehcni ehS
denrael osla dah ew ,edulerp eht nI
.keerc siht ni ehtab dluow aialA dna ogaL ,remmuS gniruD
;thgirla saw taht tub ,emit siht enola emoc dah eH
,dnabdaeh a evah t’ndid ksam ehT
,niap eht edih ot htgnerts reh lla gnisu saw ehs llet dluoc ogaL
.snommoC ’sretsilabrA eht rof kool
”.iemnoB ,nosdnarg ruoy ot ti evig ll’I
.noinU nairavoZ eht fo seimene erew ohw
?htuos eht morf saw ehs taht si sseug ym os
,xof yarg a ton saw was eh tahw
,snaigeN tsurt ot ton thguat neeb dah eh ,gnuoy yrev saw eh ecniS
.lamina dliw a ot gniklat eb ot ddo ti dnif t’ndid eh taht desirprus ,duol tuo dias ogaL
,ni depmuj dna dewollof ehs ,sdrow sih dnatsrednu dluoc xof eht fi sA
.ylleb der reh dehctulc dnah reh
.erohs eht dnuora doolb dehsalps emos ,ni llef emoS
,thguoht-flah eh ”,suolaej tsuj lla era uoY“
.ria dilos fo edam fi sa
lamina laer a no dluow ruf eht noitcerid eht ni dewolf ksam eht no snrettap ehT
peek lliw I tub ,worromot kcab emoc ll’I .yrros m’I“
.kcahs eht fo tnorf eht yb ylmrif doots neht ,sraems eht revo sknalp esool emos deppilf ylitsah eH
.ti no thgil enihs ot gninepo eht drawot ti deirrac eH
”.erom enod ev’dluoc I hsiw I“
,ssenkrad eht ot detsujda seye sih sa dna ,ni delwarc eH
.reh htaeneb dekcut ekat ot mih detnaw dah iatnoS tcejbo krad eht was eH
”,ogaL m’I-ma I .ogaL“ ”?eman ruoy si tahw ,yoB“
”.efas gniht siht peek ll’I—
.snrettap cirtemoeg ,kcalb htiw ydob reh derevoc taht sserd decal thgit-niks a gniraew eb ot demees ehS
.doolb gnitalugaoc reh revo seenk reh gniggard
,thgit ti gnisolc dna
,esproc eht ta nwod dekool eH
a dna ,sredluohs ro kcen reh dnuora ekil
.loop raelc-latsyrc eht dehcaorppa neht
,oraD rruL ,uoy knahT“
.evah dluow raeB denigami eh sa yrd flesmih koohs neht
dexaler os mih edam gnilcric citonpyh riehT
.thguoht eh ,sniatnuom eseht rof xof fo dnik drieW
.elbaresim dna das dna emoseurg ylpmis saw ti ;yracs ton saw tI
.worb denettalf eht revo gninnur doolb fo kaerts suonimo na dah tI
,ti ni dloc gnihtemos gnicalp
.laer lla saw siht taht flesmih ecnivnoc ot gniyrt fi sa
.reh rof ytip tlef ogaL
,ti revo sregnif sih nar eH
,keerc eht ot ksam eht deirrac eH
.peew ot nageb eh