,snroca htiw derettil ydaerla saw tserof kao eht tey
”.ni og ll’I ,tup yatS .roolf eht ees I kniht I“ ,dias eh ”,no dloH“
.hcum ees t’ndluoc llits yeht tub
”.gnitaroced emos esu dluoc erus ti dnA“
.ciffart pu gnidloh saw dna thguoht ni tsol neeb dah eH
,dloc naht erom saw tI .devresbo ehs
.sevruc tI .gniliec eht ta kooL“
,yb gnippots deredisnoc eH
”,ereh ni dloc yllaer s’tI“
”elavrehtiW fo floW“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.dnuora t’nerew setamssalc sih nehw tsael ta
.ylleb rieht no ni ezeeuqs ot tluda na rof ro
.gnidaoler swobssorc eht fo kciwhcthcthct eht dna
.niar remmuS thgil a retfa enotsdnas eht sa roloc emas eht erew sdnah siH
;sretaw deroloc-erhco esoht ni sehtolc sih hsaw t’ndluoc eH
,ylrae llits s’ti tsael ta ,lleW
,liaw gnirepmihw a tuo deirc ehS
”!oga shtnom rof
.doolb fo yarps a ni edis etisoppo eht no detixe dna
.esnes fo tuO .elcsum fo tuo
”elavrehtiW fo floW“ morf tprecxe na fo
.eb ot dedeen ti revetahw ro ,riahc ro ,elbat a sa evres ot ’,sretrauq gnivil‘ rieht otni pmuts eert a gniggard ,dias aialA
,dias ehs ”,tsrif ni og uoy ,ti dnuof uoy ,yeH“
.smroftalp enotsdnas dedore dna sreddal epor suoiracerp yb meht gnissecca
,aseM elavrehtiW eht ni sraey evlewt sih fo lla devil dah ogaL
.ti trats t’ndid uoy wonk I“
”,pu naelc og ll’I“
”.neht dnah a em evig ,enif ,yakO“
.dias eh ”!dekcolnu s’tI“
,setsaw nrehtron eht ni rehtraf ro
.lamina deppart a ekil gnikcik traeh sih
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
…reilrae sraey owT
.yaw taht eb ot pu worg dluow raeB sih depoh eH
.emoh saw ogaL gnisnes
”?ereh did yeht kniht uoy od tahW“ ”.gnihtyna tae ll’eH
,htron dekool ogaL
.mrots a gnithgif sessarg ekil gnidneb sreksihw reh
,hguone tsuj luos dna traeh eht pu demraw dna sevael egnaro eht hguorht tsrub nus gnitib eht
,tuo detfaw tnecs yksum A
”.sretnilps rewef ,hcnarb taht morf ti barG“
”?kniht I ?rallec a ekil s’tI“
.tcafitra tneicna eht tcetorp dna
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
.noitanimreted htiw reh dedoolf keerc ybraen a morf sretaw reicalg fo llems ehT
doolb dna trid derettalps htiw nworb won trihs eulb sih
,foor a fo ecnalbmes a ti evag yponac s’kao eht esuaceb ,keerc eht yb pu yaw kcahs dlo eht dekil htob yehT
.senim eht ta gnikrow eb dluow ehs os
.god drehpehs ylerab
,faeleriF fo htnom eht fo yad htfif eht ylno
.gniees tuohtiw ees dluoc ehs tub
.naecO suoutlumuT eht fo serohs eht otni dewolf treseD etihW eht erehw sdnal ni
.emit a ta spets eerht nwod gnippoh
.tsrif daeh gniog
”?swolloH eht ta semoh eht fo eno ekil s’ti ebyaM
.hteet sih gnittirg
,tnenitnoC najreJ eht fo tsae raf eht morf ecar a erew nirdlO ehT
,tuo detniop ogaL
,llaw enots eht ffo dils
,terref sselecarg a ekil tuo demrow ehS
,keerc laicalg gniwolf ylivaeh a tsap ,htap elbbep eht ffo tib A
.srups owt dah aialA .esrow ro ,desruc
.drows tnaig a yb dehsals neeb dah ti fi sa dekool edisffilc peets eht
”.setirps ruoy ksa dna ni oG .onnuD“
.denruter rehtaf sih erofeb sesiurb sih fo wef a pu revoc ot yaw a dnif ebyam dna
.nees reve dah seye sih thgis lufrednow tsom eht laever ot pu ti detfil dna ti koot ogaL
.snoitadnuof ysmilf no denooram doow fo sbals wef a naht erom gnihton meht fo tsom
.sloot gninim yadyreve reh fo trap—
,sevael kao gninworb eht naht rehto foor on dah erutcurts ehT
loohcs ta yad gnol a morf denruter tsuj dah eh dneterp dna editneve yb kcab eb dluoc ogaL tub ,tuoedih terces sih ot ekih a fo tib a saw tI
,ssertrof rieht no yltcerid gnillaf t’nerew syar s’hkonnuS ,noonretfa eht ni emit siht tA
.rood radec deniats ,dnuor a saw lennut eht otni teef ruoF
,daeh ym depmuB“ ”?ti si tahW“
,dum htiw sllaw gnidnats-llits eht gnitniap
.elkraps larutanrepus ylraen ,gniremmihs a ni thgil eht detcelfer slatsyrc eht
.dessarrabme eb ot deugirtni oot saw ehs tub
,yrd ot meht gnah
”.lortnoc-fles fo level emos eganam uoy sselnu snoitca ruoy dnefed ot elba eb t’now I tub
.lenap eht ta dellup dna drawrof dehcaer eH
,gnieb fo demaerd reve dik yna sa suoixonbo dna duol sa eb dluoc yeht ,evaC dnomaiD rieht nI
”—pord gol eht tel uoY“
,iraaV oehT fo eciov eht emac ”!nwod ,raeB“
,krad ylsuoegrog saw niks s’aialA
.kcahs eht fo llaw kcab eht tsniaga ylduol gnihsams ,revo deppit gol decnalab ylsuoiracerp eht ,dias taht htiw dnA
.ti fo tnorf ni ecneserp citehtapmys a desnes xof yarg ehT .nibac dlo elkcahsmar a yal liart elbbep esool a nwoD
,sevorg kao eht drawot deps ehs llihnwoD
.skcab rieht no laoc fo seldnub yrrac ro ,kcip a ,pmal a tfil ot hguone dlo erew yeht sa noos sa krow ot detrats ohw
”,won rallec ruo s’ti ,lleW“
,secnatsmucric lamron ni dnas deroloc-thgil fo sniarg naht erom gnihtyna ekil kool t’ndluow yehT
.aialA degru ogaL ”,pmal ruoy teG“
.sroloc gnignahc ylluf erew sevael eht dna
,hsa cinaclov desserpmoc morf demrof dah atarts mottob ehT
.gol eht fo dne sih pu dekcip dna erutsop sih dexif ogaL
,enaL enotsenuR ssorc ot ecnahc sih rof detiaw eh sA
.redluob citinarg eht fo ecaf eht otni thgir gnidael rettuhs a saw ereht fi sa
.esor yrotavresbO aseM eht fo rewot lanogatco eht erehw
,ti morf gnitaidar snrettap xelpmoc ni riah reh diarb dluow ehs
.tsujda seye sih tel eh sa detniuqs ogaL
.evaC dnomaiD sih ot og dluow eh
”?ti tup ew od erehW“
.eugnot nirdlO s’aialA ni rehtorb regnuoy rof drow eht saw ilowG ”?ilowG ,ti htiw em pleh ot eraC“
,niaga esool tel neeb dah ti
.emoh deroloc-tsur sih fo tnorf ni elpam dekoorc ,dlo eht ot deit trac dellup-uobirac a was dna teertS ralhsA fo renroc eht denrut eH .netfo—
.reh dniheb liart der a gnivael
levon lluf eht teg nac uoy tub
,ssalg derettahs fo sdrahs kciht
,detacol erew senim laoc eht erehw
noitazilivic a yb devrac ,gnillewd tneicna na saw tI
,won yb enog lla erew serusaert dlo ehT
,selbategev toor delkcip rof dessap ev’thgim tniop emos ta tahw htiw deffuts raj deirub-flah eno dna
.regnol yna ytisoiruc reh niatnoc ot elbanu ,deksa aialA ”?ereht ni s’tahW“
.eert kao dlo na rednu gnidih nibac nekasrof a fo sniamer eht dehcaorppa dna maerts raelc eht ssorc ot skcor lausu eht no deppiks ogaL
,lennut dnuor yltcefrep a saw kcor eht fo ecaf eht otni devraC
reh dniheb sdnuohxof eht fo lwoh eht gniraeh
,nmutuA-dim saw tI
.sirroB ot ti evig dna ti htiw llor daerb a ekam dluohs eW“
,eb ot desu ecnartne eht erehw etacidni ot naht rehto esoprup on devres taht rood a dna
,egnahc meht gnileef dna stnemides derutxet eht revo spitregnif suoiruc sih gninnur
”?latsedep a ekil ,pmuts eht fo pot nO“ .deksa eh
,thguoht eh ,ylrae emoh s’eH
.tib a mih esaet ot dekil dna
,dehcnilf ogaL .deksa ehs
,drawtuo dekop senob elkcunk rieht semitemos ,swoble rieht fo tuo werg srups semitemoS
.redluob suomrone na yb detroppus ,tcatni yltsom llits saw kcahs eht fo llaw kcab eht ylnO
.no desserp ylgnihcnilfnu ehs ,taorht reh ni traeh reh htiW
.noitalletsnoc yreif a ekil dewolg seloh eht nehw ,thgin ta ylralucitrap
,noinU nairavoZ eht ni sevals yltcaxe t’nerew yehT
,flesti asem eht fo noitamrof evisserpmi eht fo esuaceb ylno ton
.sraey fo snoillim revo stekcop fo sderdnuh otni niar dna dniw yb devrac
,nwot gniggol tcnufed won eht tliub ohw elpoep eht yb dnuof saw gnillewd eht ,retal sraey fo sdnasuohT
,dnuorg ydnas eht dehcuot yeht litnu smra sih derewol eH
.diuqil dibrut eht hguorht enihs thgilpmal eht gnittel
.niks knip ,rednet gnilaever
,redluohs sih revo gab eht gnuws ogaL
,reh dnuora tserof eht fo ygrene eht tlef ehS
”.ti fo emos etsat meht evah llew sa thgiM
.gol yklub eht detfil yeht ,rehtegoT
.ssenisub etavirp sih otni gnikeep reh gnitnaw ton ,sdnah reh morf gab eht dellup yltpurba ogaL
,god.ecioveht ta
,sllarevo reh htaeneb kcab reh ta egdir eht tpek aialA hguohtla dna
,hgih shtdaerbregnif owt ylno rups ekil-nroh ,dednuor a saw dnoces ehT
,erew yeht yaw eht tsuj saw tI
.skcahs tcilered erom wef a erew
.resiw eht enon eb dluow rehtaf sih—
.llor ysmulc a ni delppot dna ylitsah oot tib a ni deppord ehS
,ti dniheb kcuns eh ,yb dessap nogaw txen eht nehW
.dlo sraey owt ylno saw ehs nehw navarac eegufer a htiw devirra dah aialA
,delley tnahcrem a ”!ogaL yeH“
,nrob saw ogaL erofeb snoitareneg denodnaba
;enilriah reh woleb tsuj
.nosaes eht rettam on ,euqserutcip syawla saw taht htap niatnuom a
.seye s’rethguad reh morf dehsiugnitxe thgil eht dessentiw ehs sa riapsed ni deirc dah ,devalsne dna deredrum ebirt reh nees dah ehS
,nwo sih t’nsaw doolb eht fo tsom wenk eh tub—
seirots tsohg fo dekeer syawhcra devrac-enur dna ,syawegassap ymoolg ,segdirb suorehcaert ehT
,tegrat rieht dessim ylworran sworra eerhT !kcawhT .pmuwhT .pmuwhT
.raeb laer a nees reven dah ogaL
.noitautis yna fo tuo tseb eht ekam dluoc dna ,citsinutroppo
,suoigatnoc eb thgim srups eht gnikniht
.serusaert tneicna fo esimorp eht dna
.rettam t’ndid taht tub ,sdnomaid fo edam t’nsaw evac ehT
”.yawa deirrac oot tib a teg uoy taht si gniyas m’I llA
.hserf doof peek oT“ .desseug ogaL
,no kcab sevolg gnikrow reh tup ehS
,nirdlO erew srekrow enim eht lla ylraeN
,smra fo staoc denigami rieht fo srennab sa sgar nrot gnignah
.ycavirp fo ria na sredluob ybraen eht dna
,reh htiw lanosrep erom tib a eb dluoc eh tlef ogaL tub
,daeherof reh fo edis thgir eht morf tuo gnikop
,keerc eht morf deucser
,nac I tahw pu denaelc I“
.delwoh sdnuoh ehT
.moorssalc eht otni dum taht gniggard ton era uoY“
;lairosseforp yltcaxe kool ton did ehs
.drawrof reh degru dna niap reh derahs—
;kcab reh fo llams eht ot gnidnetxe dna sedalb redluohs reh neewteb gnitrats
,seenk rieht no ni lwarc ot dlihc a rof hguone ediw tsuj
,reporp elavrehtiW naht retteb hcum dekool aseM elavrehtiW eht thguoht eH
.elims decrof a otni spil reh fo renroc eht dekaewt atsyrC
”.dloc os ti speek taht keerc eht morf retaw eht eb tsuM
.liaf ot reh rof tnatropmi oot saw ksat reH
.daor yddum a no lepuarg hserf ekil
.ytrevop dna modeerf ni gniworg dik a gnieb fo serutnevda eht dna senim eht ta efil eht saw wenk ehs lla ,dnalemoh ron stnerap reh gnirebmemer toN
,ereht ssertrof rieht tliub yehT
.srups dellac yeht hcihw ,seidob rieht no secnarebutorp ynob gniworg fo tiart etanutrofnu eht dah yehT
.daD regdaB yldduC eht ,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
.ylleb reh no tuc naelc a gniraet
retfihsepahs dlo eht sretnuocne ogaL nehw
,knalF tsaE eht no saw loohcs s’ogaL
,rehtaf elitalov sih htiw noitatnorfnoc fo tros yna diova ot derreferp ogaL
dne yrev eht ot hguorht hsup dluow ehS
:sehtolc sih dna flesmih naelc ot og dluoc eh erehw yltcaxe wenk eH .thguoht eh
.htaptoof niatnuom eht drawot dellorts dna ,ecnef retemirep eht revo deppoh ,senim laoc eht dnoyeb tsew rehtraf deretnuas eH
.neeb evah llew sa thgim yeht
.dewollof tceffe thgil evitcelfer eht
,asem eht fo tniop tsehgih eht drawot
segap eht hguorht gnippilf fi sa meht nihtiw desserpmoc emit eht gnirolpxe ,reyal yb reyal
.erutseg ylrehtom a ni daeh reh detlit atsyrC
,edih ot ecalp a dnuof xof eht sselnU
,oga sraey owt ,erehw saw sihT
selbbep deroloc-itlum htiw snoitadnuof nekorb eht gnitaroced
.ylsseldnuos ylraen derettum aialA
”.sruoy si siht eveileb I ,ereH“
.lehctas dezinagrosid yllacitoahc reh ron triks reh fo roloc eht rehtien dehctam dna ezis gnorw eht fo saw esuolb reh revo taoc eht
;bonkrood reppoc ,dedorroc eht dehcaer eh litnu seenk sih no drawrof gnihcni
,emit txen ni enuT
”!daehbun uoy ,kcab ruoy morf tfil t’noD !sgel ruoy morF“
.eloh eht otni llef yllacitcarp ogaL dna redrah dehsup aialA ”—hsup t’nod—“
.yreviled wen a nettog ev’tsum eH
.etisbew s’níuqaoJ no
,sretnalp dnuora gnieotpit
,sedalb redluohs reh evoba niks eht tih driht eht tub
.ecalptekram eht drawot trac sih gnivird
gnitaeb hserf a teg neve ebyam—
aipotooZ ekil smlif ni yensiD ta krow sih rof nwonk
,drawni gnuws ylneddus llaw eht fo noitrop erauqs A
.loohcs ta elbuort ni nettog d’eh taht dezafnu demees eH
.pup a ,llew ,sa elbaticxe ylisae sa dna citegrene saw raeB
.thguoht eh ,kcor a edisni deppart yks thgin eht dnuof eW
.enot laitnerever ylraen a ni deilper eh ”?siht ees uoy t’naC“
,srats gninihs fo emod a ta pu gnirats saw eH
.trihs eulb sih no tops naelc eno eht no dum eht depiw ehS
”,keerc eht yb eno yvaeh a s’erehT“
.yaw eht gnidael ,detseggus ehs
.llaw enotsdnas eht ot depeerc eh sa
.emoh deirruh neht
,tloH rosseforP reh dellac stneduts tsoM .dias eh
,seloh eht morf drawpu deraems toos kcalb fo sliarT
,deilper yletilop ogaL
,swolloH eht sa nwonk saw doohrobhgien sihT
.kcab gnikool tuohtiw eybdoog gnivaw ,sdnuorg loohcs eht morf dehsur dna
,snibac tneicna fo sniamer derettacs fo dleif a dehcaer ogaL .emoc ot nmutuA repeed a fo esimorp a htiw
.lacitrev saw gol eht litnu pu dne sih hsup ogaL depleh dna nwod gol eht fo edis reh detcerid ehS
.retlaf ton did ehs ,llits tey
.pmuht a htiw pmuts reh gnippord ,dias aialA
.nees gnieb tuohtiw gnipacse
,tuo yllihc tib a saw ti hguohT
,nnajuW mletS eht ni devil ylno yeht draeh eH
.nepo dekaeuqs ti drawni dna ,dekcolnu rood eht kcilc gniyfsitas a htiw tub
.ekoms gnitaeh dna gnikooc fo seirutnec morf pu tliub
.noitcefrep saw tI
.detluxe ogaL ”!evac dnomaid a dnuof eW !sdnomaid ekil s’tI“
,llaw gniniater a otno deppoh ogaL
.bun elttil reh morf gnidaerps saw selkraps fo noisolpxe na fi sa
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.nemiceps suonimo na gnitatseg
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,seloh hguone-egral yna edisni semoh edurc rieht edam srenim erehw
,lanac eganiard a no flesmih decnalab ogaL ,enaL enotsenuR no nosib dna ,uobirac ,nexoksum fo ciffart gnipmots eht diova oT
,ogaL detcerroc ehs
,ti tuoba gnihton od t’nod I fI“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.denekrad ylneddus evac ehT ”.enif lla
.nettogrof ,yrd ,tneicna
’.sretsis neetriht‘ reh meht dellac ehs
,eci sa dloc ,dnuor saw ti
,ttum yltsom s’ogaL saw raeB .dias raeB
.tceffe eht hctac ot reh rof thgir tsuj delgna thgil eht neht dna ”—I tub ecin s’tI“
.yb gnissap tsuj saw eh
”.lausu naht dedaeh-ytpme erom kool uoY“ .derepsihw aialA
,sseneuqinu rieht htiw elbatrofmocnu tlef secar rehto tub
.stfihs reh htiw enod saw ehs retfa erom neve denekrad netfo
.sehcnarb s’kao eht morf ssalg fo sdrahs gnirettilg gnignah dna
hturt eht dih ro—
”elavrehtiW fo floW“   yojne esaelP
,rellat shtdaerbregnif owt dna
strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”?…taht si tahw ,ilowG“
,senim laoc eht ta dekrow ohw nirdlO tsom fo snoixelpmoc evilo dna eznorb eht ekilnU
eert tsellat eht ot etim tsellams eht morf—
.mih dnuora sniatnuom eht fo yna naht rellat dna reneerg gnihcterts
,kaerb dluow bonkrood eht diarfa saw eH
.ssorca denetsah eH
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
.ti revo eveels yhtlif eht dellup dna woble sih dnuora ezuag a depparw ehS
”.evirra arbmU fo stsim eht erofeb ecalap siht gnidliub enod eb ll’eW
?worrom eht ni tnet eht yb pots ot oehT ksa uoy dluoC“
.sdnah sih fo hcaer eht dnoyeb tsuj snoitalletsnoc gnilkraps ta
”,yretnilps os ton s’eno sihT“
,nwot gniggol a fo etis eht saw sihT
”,atsyrC ,uoy knahT“
”?pu hsaw dna emoh og uoy t’nod yhW
,htaerb fo tuo nur dluow ehs
,llaw eht ot denettalf ogaL .srettuhs eht demmals dna ,ni mih deggard
.keerC erO pu deitrid taht sgniliat fo sdnuom gnillips
,mih drawot dehsur ehS .yob A
reh fo tnorf ni pmal latem a htiw ni kcab gnipeerc emac neht
:lufituaeb ylbanoitseuqnu ti edam taht yaw a ni deyalpsid ehs daeh reh no rups eht
.aialA ,dneirf tseb s’ogaL devil seloh eseht fo eno nI
.asem eht fo sdnuorg niam eht woleb teef fo sderdnuh
,reh ot raelc saw daeha htap ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.yawa detnirps dna tuo dekans xof ehT
deksa eh sklis meht lla toG
,sevorg kao eht drawot dednecsa liart elbbep esool ehT
”?bonkrood a nrut ekans a dluow woH“
,noitingocer dnoyeb detsur slisnetu nori
,seitriht etal reh ni erehwemos saw ehS
.dnah ytrid a kcab dellup dna slruc krad s’ogaL delffur ehS
.redluohs s’ogaL gnipmub
,niwdlaB níuqaoJ yb
.rallec a otni ecaps depahs-emod eht desopruper ohw
sehcnarb enip fo erutamra na ni dednepsus teknalb netae-htom a htiw tnet a dehctip aialA .iraaV ogaL :srettel etihw ,dlob ni llaw eht no eman sih detniap dna senocenip evitcetorp htiw dnuorg eht derettil eH
diulf citoinma na ot resolc saw won yb tub
.stac gnilworp dna sevod tnelonmos ffo gniracs
,liat eht yb mih dehctans oehT tub ,tuo yaw sih walc ot deirt raeB .rehtaf s’ogaL
,erew yeht dekrowrevo dna diaprednu woh htiw tub
,ylluferac ti denrut eH
,ecno erifnob a til neve dna ,pissog s’nwot eht derahs ,semag pu edam meht fo owt ehT
,dum htiw dekac saw riah ylruc s’ogaL
,segnih neddih no detnuom saw lenap nedoow ehT
.sgar yddum ruoy tuoba od nac I gnihton s’ereht tub
.spitregnif sih htaeneb ffo ekalf anitap laet eht gnileef
.llafnwoD eht erofeb morf
,noitsuahxe htiw yvaeh erew seye reH
”.lennut terces a ekil s’tI“
.yawyna dum eht ni pu dne I neht
.krims ykcoc ,duorp sih tpek eh os
,niwdlaB níuqaoJ yb
.suoicoref dna elbazis erew yeht wenk eh tub
.tuoba dam ylgnikoj llits saw ehs eno
,senob lanretxe rieht edih ot elbissop gnihtyreve did nirdlO tsoM
.tserof eht dnuora gniyrd dnuof d’ehs serah dna ,sexof ,slerriuqs fo senob eht htiw edis reh detaroced dna
.agaS ssoN eht dellac seires ysatnaf nwo sih gnitirw yltnerruc dna
.ssertrof rieht otni doow fo knuhc eht yrrac ot deganam yeht tub ,llihpu elggurts gnitsuahxe na saw tI
.flesym gnidnefed tsuj saw I !ti detrats yehT“
”!devresed yeht tahw—tahw tog yehT
.oga gnol nwod delppot dah ti fo edis rehtie no sllaw eht taht nevig
,yad yreve loohcs retfa dekrow atsyrC erehw saw sihT
”.dnekeew ruoy yojne dnA
.nips tnageleni na ni smra reh gnivaw ,dias aialA
,kool esraoc ,derutxet a ruf sih evag taht sehctolps etihw nevenu htiw ,nworb saw taoc siH
!ffworr ,ffoor rrA .wodniw nepo eht hguorht dekeep ylluferac eH
.sredluohs ro ,selkna ,seenk ,slluks rieht no spmub ekil-nroh tuorps dluow yeht ro
;seye reh morf yawa riah nrubua fo dnarts a dehsup ehs regnif yddum a htiW
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA  .dnuora retnec lliw levon eht fo tser eht
,semarf wodniw fo yromem tnacs a
,enips reh morf gnidurtorp senob neetriht fo egdir a saw tsrif ehT
”?thgirla uoy erA“
:dnuorg eht derettil srenwo suoiverp eht yb tfel sirbeD
.wodahs ni sevlesmeht dnuof yeht os
.llafnwoD eht erofeb morf noitazilivic a fo snoitadnuof eht revo tliub saw ytic eht esuaceb tub
.gniliec wol eht no daeh sih gniparcs ,deirc eh ”!tihS“
,ni gnilwarc saw aialA
.sehtolc yhtlif hcus ni mih dnuof rehtaf sih fi—
,mih fo tnorf ni yltcaxe pmal eht dleh ogaL nehw tub
,stnemrag sih hsaw ot emit dah eh os ,gninromdim ylno saw ti ,ylikcuL
,detrulb ehs ”!tihS“ .ssecorp eht ni daeh reh gnittih osla ,etasnepmoc ot tsaf doots ehS
.thgil ecracs eht gnikcolb
”?meht no hguor os og ot deen uoy od seman owt s’hkaT ni yhw tsuJ“
.sega eht revo pu tliub slatsyrc hcir-muiclac elpmis erew srats ehT
”—saw I ,edis ruoy no llef tI“
”,ybab daed a ekil skool tI“
.hgis a ni detalfed ehS
,emoD ssalgnA tnatsid eht ot thgis fo enil raelc a dna
tserof eht ni msinagro yreve ot snoitcennoc eht fi sa
,daeh sih ot noitisop evitaler emas eht ni pmal eht dleh eh sa gnol sA
.llems cirtcele ,prahs a dah dna
”.tey emit hcnul neve ton s’ti tuB“
.noitanigami s’dlihc a pots t’ndluoc taht tub
”.ereht evil setirps tserof ebyaM“
,dessim sworra owT !duhT .piwF .piwF
.pihs duorp a fo worp eht ekil tnals llihpu na ni gnihcterts ,ilé’aC mletS citinarg eht morf drawhtron dednetxe taht porctuo enotsdnas a no tliub ytic tniauq a
.mih ot ti dnah ot gab rehtael dezisrevo sih rof dehcaer ehS
,gnitsujda erew seye riehT
,serats gnigduj dna gnitib reh morf edisa dna
.tuoedih terces rieht hsillebme ot dnif dluoc yeht revetahw dna ,selttob ,skcor ni thguorb meht fo owt eht ,dnekeew yrevE
”,mauT rroL ,sknahT .wonk daD tel ll’I“
,detcepxe dah eh naht od ot redrah saw tahT
.deksa ogaL ”?kcor a tsniaga wodniw a tup yeht dluow yhW“
.gol wolloh a otni ydob derit reh delggirw dna snref htaeneb dedilg ehS
.somsoc etavirp rieht ni enola
,lacigam dekool ti thguoht ogaL
’.bun‘ reh eno taht dellac ehs
deil dna od dluow ecalp sih ni dik yna tahw did eh os
,ecnenimorp enotsdnas eht otni yltcerid devrac sriats eht koot eH
.ylsuoethgir oot tib a ,dias eh
.erow sralohcs elamef eht nub yramotsuc eht ni deit fo daetsni
.doow deretnilps eht dna trid eht otni sevlesmeht gnigdol
,wodahs s’lwo na sa teiuq swap reh ,tserof eht hguorht delf xof yarg ehT  2 fo 1 traP
.yrtemoeg fo esnes debrutrep yletisiuqxe na htiw psaw neila na fo sevih eht ekil dekool noitamrof elohw ehT
.meht gnitsat neht ,gniliec eht no slatsyrc ytlas eht ta regnif a gnibbad ,deksa aialA
.thgin eht otni etal netfo
.koob tneicna tsom a fo
.tsetal eht ta yaduhK ro ,yadnooM no kcab koob eht gnirb ll’I esimorp I dna“ ,dias ogaL
,yadugnO ylno saw ti tub
,tnecsed sih nageb dna asem eht fo egde eht dehcaer eH
,wodniw eht ot pu daeh sih deppop pup dlo-htnom-eerht ehT
,nemodba reh yb deparcs worra rehtonA !pahW
.mih evoba dereep dna flesmih dnuora smra sih depparw ogaL .digirf saw ti
,niwdlaB níuqaoJ yb
”.keew txen ssalc ni kcab uoy ees ll’I
.evaC dnomaiD rieht dnuof aialA dna ogaL
ksam ekil-flow ,lacigam eht tuoba snrael dna
.eloh eht drawot ogaL gnihsup
,asem eht fo tsew nwotytnahs eht hguorht deunitnoc ogaL
.wols ton did ehs ,niap gniraet eht etipseD
,ria eht detaemrep nori fo llems ehT
.ruf etihw dna ,egnaro ,yarg reh gnilgnit yticirtcele ekil
,srehtaef tnecsediri ro acim fo skcelf htiw sdiarb reh gninroda
,ogaL naht redlo sraey owt saw ehS
”!pu til lla ti ,aohW“
.niaga taht deirt reven yeht taht esned os tog ekoms eht hguoht
,ni debmilc dna bewredips ytsud a edisa dehsurb eH
,reh no desu ecno dah eh tlusni eht gnisu
,ti hguorht decils
.doow fo sbals dna skcirb enotsdnas htiw trof erutainim a tliub eh erehw ,edis tfel eht koot ogaL
.ti htiw emit ruoy ekaT“ ”.enod tsomla m’I
,yrots eht fo sretpahc wef tsrif eht serutaef elavrehtiW fo floW fo tprecxe sihT
,citsimitpo saw ehS
”.ekans tnaig a rO“
,mraerof s’ogaL no gar tew a depiw tloH atsyrC rosseforP .niagA
,dekwauqs namow decaf-tnuag a
.citatsce erom sdnuoh eht fo seirc eht gniredner
,efil suoiverp a ni flehs a neeb ev’tsum taht doow fo sknalp
!slliks noitcurtsnoc gnidnatstuO“
.ylduorp doots neht ,gorf a ekil hguorht sgel sih dellup neht
,ssalc retfa stnerap s’neliaW dna s’sirroB ot klat ll’I“
elbuort peed ni teg dluow eh wenk eH
.kaerc gniugirtni na htiw gnitnuat
:asem eht fo ecaf nretsew eht drawot dereep eH
.slian ytsur dna sretnilps rieht gnihsalf yb nerdlihc suoveihcsim morf sevlesmeht detcetorp sgnidliub detadipalid fo snoteleks erehw
,dias dna sllarevo s’renim reh no sparts eht dexif
knalF tsaE eht fo weiv eye-s’drib a mih evag taht egdirb enots a ot debmilc neht
.lluf ni nepo gnuws lenap eht tub ,detsetorp segnih dlo ehT
”!?tahw ro gnissorc eY“