.dniheb tfel yeht seiromem eht dna ,skcab rieht no sehtolc eht ,spil rieht no sdrow ehT
ro efas neeb evah yeht
dluow yeht esuaceb emoh wen rieht eb dluow sniatnuom esehT
.dloh dluow gnidnib epor eht depoh eH .emit eht dah dah eh nehw
.snosaes fo tfihs eht kram ot fi sa
deirrac eh thgiew eht fo nedrub eht dna
.ynam woh yltcaxe fo tnuoc tsol dah eH
.erif dercas eht morf sehsa eht fo stnanmer eht ekil
,swodahs rieht fo segde eht morf
.dnal eht otni gniknis doolb dna skram kcalb
wonk mih tel dna sdrib railimaf fo sgnos eht tuo dekcip srae sih yaw ehT
yeht sa edirts yreve htiw denrub selcsum siH
.mih htaenrednu koohs dah dnalsi ehT
.mrots a retfa taolf eht riaper ot dah eh semit eht fo kcart tsol eH
.daed ydaerla saw eh ekil relevarT ehT fo ekops yehT
.meht hcaer ton dluoc sduolc eht
.mih revo llor feirg fo evaw rehtona tlef eh sa
,roliaS ehT fo senob eht hguorht delttar tloj digirf neddus A
.kcab meht devol ti wonk meht tel dna
,syawla sa emas eht
tuoba klat srehto ot denetsil dna
.taht naht noitcerid erom elttil htiw dna
.stnemele lacitsatnaf ro dnarg on htiw yrots lacirotsih drawrof-thgiarts yrev a si yrots lanigiro ehT
,srats eht ees dluoc eh pot niatnuom eht ot emac eh sA
.erom elttil a fi
.doots eh hcihw no teef gnihca eht morf
.raen saw emoh
,devivrus yeht sa gnol sA
sllih hguorht meht del eH
,pmac fo egde eht no tsuj syawlA
.relevarT ehT emaceb dna
.snoitcerid dna seilppus rof egnahcxe ni daor eht no ekam dluoc yeht stfarc tahw gnidart
.ekanselttar taerg a
.tnaem dniheb taht lla gnivael tahw
.srehto ot eman sti sa
.meht neewteb retaw tup eh litnu sgnul sih ni gnittiS
.luferac dna wols
,sevlesmeht eb dluow yehT
,niaga relevarT ehT emaceb eh nehW
.evom ot yvaeh ti edam dna nwod mih dehgiew dah tI
,tser ot thgir eht rof ydob sih no sdnuow
.ylimaf dna sdneirf sih fo ytefas eht fo tuo mih dael ot tpmetta na ni raed dleh eh esoht fo secaf eht erow yeht semitemoS
dniheb eman taht tfel roliaS ehT oS
,naeco eht rof edam seonac regral
erutuf eht fo htaed eht rof denruom eH
. sniktA ”inohaS“ raG yb  seltruT tnaiG fo dnaL eht morf elixE
.mih erofeb srehtaf ’srotsecna sih fo snoitareneg dna rehtaf sih fo ecalp ehT
.tilps ti sa rehsif eht htaenrednu gnignahc
.emoh ton saw ti tuB
denrael eh sa werg
,nus eht ni dexelf tI
?dlot yeht seirots eht dnatsrednu yeht dluoW ?meht gnas yeht yhw dna sgnos emas eht wonk yeht dluow sgniht eseht tuohtiw ,devivrus yeht fi nevE
,htiw delevart eh esoht fo seye eht ni ti ees dluoc eH
,deppils dna knus dah tI
.evom ot gnidiced no saw dnalsi eht eltrut tnaig eht tsuj saw ti taht mih dlot dna
.erom devaS .erom enod evah dluoc eh dehsiw roliaS ehT
.yalp seltrut tnaig eht erehw ot sretaw sti otni evod eh sa tlef eh feiler eht dna niks sih
.nwonknu dna regnad otni tuo gnihsup erofeb
.derettefnu hguorht decar dniw eht dna seert sa llat sa erew sevael eht
.skcit dna seotiuqsom ot mih gnirapmoc elihw
hgih saw noitarbelec ehT
,sgniht eseht rof sdrow eht rof esu a dah regnol on elpoep sih nehw ,yademoS
tnereffid neeb dah tahW
esu dluow eh tahw s’taht
.wen t’nsaw ekauqhtrae nA
.dluoc yeht tahw ekat dna hctans ot ydaer gnileef
,tib elttil a rof tsael ta
mih sa aedi emas eht dah ohw srehsif rehto taht tsuJ
taeb drawrof ydaets eht htiW
.rehtaef dna ,fooh
.hguone ylsuoituac ,hguone ylkciuq evom t’ndid ohw esoht
noitasnes taht rof snosaer ylekil erom rehto
.pets txen eht koot eh dna
.gnihtyna naht erom
.esle gnihtyna naht redlo gnos a gnis ti ot denetsil dna
.emoh rieht ton saw siht tuB
peelsa llef yeht nehw tlef
htroN ecalpemos dednal dah neves ehT
.derit gnieb fo derit saw eH
noitcelloc ygolohtna eht ni yrots siht dnif nac uoY
,nwo s’roliaS ehT naht repeed seiromem dednuow htiw
?seltrut tnaig tuohtiW
.ees ot tey dah yeht sgniht fo seirots gnillet ,gnignis ,gnittuC
.flesti no ni gnispalloc esuoh sih fo kcarc detaeh eht htiw gnirepsihW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,hcaeb eht no despalloc esoht gniees derebmemer eH
,erom gnihtemos rof sdees eht meht htiw deirrac yehT
ti ees dluoc yeht
?seugnot rieht no tiurf hserf eht fo
semag sih dnif osla nac uoy dna
,gnihtyreve etipsed ,flesmih dnuof relevarT ehT
revol dlo sih tuoba seirots dlot rehtnap wen ehT .evila meht peek
,traeh sih dnuora hcaer mih edisni deirrac eh sduolc eht fo dnuow gniwalc eht tlef relevarT ehT
.rednimer a ekil ydob sih ot gnulc llits toos nehsa tahT
dluoc eH .dnah dereffo na ,meht neewteb tfig erusnu nA
?emoh dellac yeht dnalsi eht tuohtiw eb yeht dluow elpoep fo tros tahW
niatnuom a fo pot eht ot emac eH
emoh rieht koot taht sduolc eht ees llits dluoc yeht dna
.ycrem a dna stfig erew yeht tahT
si yrots s’yadot dna
,srewsna on dereffo mih evag ti egdelwonk ehT
.taht nihtiw dnuof trofmoc eht dna
.htaerb ykahs a fo troffe dna emit eht lla htiw
.hcaeb eht no ydob rehtona neeb evah dluow eh dna retal dnoces a tuB
?evah yeht did erutuf tahW
.elpoep a sa nigiro ruo fo trap sa dedrager si dna yrotsih laro
gnivael saw eh desoppus eH .edilsdnal
?nruom dluoc eh os noituloser mirg a ro
.feirg fo edistuo snoitome derebmemer eh taht hguonE
thgiew eht tlef eh sa dehcrul hcamots siH .dluoc reven dna
.telracs fo sespmilg esoht esahc ot
?mih dnatsrednu yeht dluow
,duol tuo daer eb ot tnaem yrots a si sihT
.htrib sih fo dnal eht ot toN
.mih fo tuo efil eht elgnarts ot deirt dna taorht sih dnuora sregnif sti depparw taht duolc lufetah A
erutuf eht ni dna
.hcum yawa evig t’ndid tuo ekam dluoc eh setteuohlis ehT
.nrut ni sregnarts sa meht dedrager taht sregnarts ynam ot emoh erew spmaws dna sehsram ehT
.yats t’ndluoc yeht wenk yeht tub
.ograc sti rof eligarf oot raf saw eonac eht llew oot lla wenk eH
denrael yeht ,htron dloc eht nI .ecaep ton fi
no evil dluow syoj dna ,selggurts ,sgnos riehT
.dleh ti elpoep eht rof moor hguone yldrah dna ydaets ot taolf a htiw lessev lluh elgnis A
.sretsiS eviF eht yb detfig erew yeht taht seno eht dna
,igalasT ni ti raeh uoy nehw ,noitpircsnart a sa daer yrd a ekam thgim ti elihw dnA
won wenk eh lla
.sniatnuom eht no tcepxe dluoc yeht
.ydob sih fo sdneb eht otni dnuorg tlas sa srewolf detnawnu ekil niks sih otno demoolb sesiurB .truh roliaS ehT
.ekauqhtrae na yb pu nekow neeb dah eh
.dluoc yeht tahw ot thgit sa tsuj gnignilc dna deldduh
fo yromem ehT
.naeco nepo eht fo sregnad eht otni tfird enola tel
.sniatnuom tsedlo eht ni meht htiw eb llits dluow seltrut tnaig fo dnal eht
,wenk eh ,wohemos dna
spag eht llif ot ni dehsur naeco eht morf retaW
.nosiop denrut yllanoitnetni enicidem a ekil rettib
.meht rof dleh erutuf eht tahw tuoba snalp edam yehT .erif dercas a til yehT
.nrut ni mih rebmemer dluow dnal eht fi wonk ot denraey eH
.erac ot syaw wen dnuof dna tliub yehT
.emoc ot stnemom eht ni daed sa doog sa ro daeD .despalloc dah efas erew srehto erus gnikam tuohtiw evom ot desufer ro ykculnu oot
.ssom dna wons eht nekcalb t’ndid
.seltruT tnaiG fo dnaL eht morf elixe s’renetsiL ehT ecnis sraey neeb dah ti noos dna dessap dah emiT
.semaG floW elbmarB ,oi.hcti sih no
.meht ot pu saw meht htiw did yeht tahW
esimorp cihtapelet nekopsnu nA
.sevlesmeht deef dna strad noihsaf ot woh meht dewohs yehT
.yad rehtona ot ti ekam ot hguone tsuj saw ti fi derednow eH
.snaem yrots siht tahw fo emos tsuj derutpac I epoh tsuj I
.nrael dluow yehT .sekatsim ekam dluow yehT
,derettam taht spihsnoitaler dna snossel eht meht htiw deirrac yeht sa gnol sA
,hcram s’elpoep sih fo
thguorb eh stnirptoof ehT
fo noitazilaer eht ot emac eh sa
.ekil dekool erutuf eht tahw wonk t’ndid relevarT ehT
,ruf detuorps yeht sa hsa gniddehs
.dlihc a sa rof dnal eht dekrow eh
emit tsrif eht derebmemer eH .sretsasid rojam dna sromert fo erahs sih hguorht devil dah roliaS ehT
.tnemom taht ni dedeen yeht tahw s’taht esuaceb tsuj ebyaM
.sduolc s’niatnuom eht yb tsac kaolc eht yb tuo dekcalb erew etagivan ot derahs yeht
.wonk did eh sgniht eht fo ytilibisnopser dna
.htaerb gnilttar dna snrub eht rof lufknaht eb dluohs eh taht dna
mih tsniaga ti leef dluoc eh dehsiw eH
.tser ot ecalp a dedeen eh wenk eH
.llet ot elbissopmi saw tI
t’ndid eh fi eid dluow yehT
.llew sa dniheb seiromem esoht
.srevir ni hsif dluoc yeht taht dnA
.dniheb tfel eh ylimaf fo hself eht ekil gnillemS
dloc hsrah eht evivrus ot woh dna ,gniyas erew slamina eht tahw
,ereht tuo llits erew yeht epoh gnignol a evah ot retteb ti saW
.senob eht ni tlef eb nac taht txetnoc nekopsnu dna noitome fo level a si ereht
.enigami dluoc eh sa raf sa tuo gnihcterts dna hgih stluav neveS
,meht htiw deirrac yeht seno eht htob
,tnew eh reverehw
.erew llits yeht ereht tuo erehwemos depoh mih fo trap llams emos seno emas eht
.dlohserht neesnu emos ssorc ot gninetaerht
eugnot sih no ekoms eht etsat yllacitcarp
.spihs esoht fo eno no saw revoL siH fi derednow mih fo trap emoS
.psarg terces sti morf
.gnikam no dennalp dah roliaS ehT yenruoj a neeb t’ndah sihT
.meht dniheb deggard yeht senob fo elip taht nioj d’eh resolc teg sduolc esoht tel eh fi wenk eh tub
,woleb syellav eht ni niks dlo sti fo eerf edils ti dehctaw eH
.dah dnal eht dna eh pihsnoitaler eht liops ot gnihtemos did eh fi
.meht erofeb srotsecna fo snoitareneg eht dna srotsecna sih deirrac ohw seno eht eb dluow yehT .os ti ekam
,sedisni eht dewolloh yeht nehw morf
.yrrac ot dewolla neeb dah yeht tahw dna meht saw
dluow taht epoh eht ni meht htiw ereht eb ton dluoc taht elpoep tuoba seirots dlot yehT
,drawrof dehsup dah relevarT ehT
.ssarg eht ni sgniht ytterp devaew dna snaidraug tnelis ekil doots olaffub erehW
.efink sti fo edalb eht yteixna
,evitcepsrep lanosrep eht ,stnemele lacitsatnaf ,gib eht
mih morf yawa dellup neeb dah ti dna lanosrep os dnob a saw sihT
.mrots siht tsniaga mih ecarb oT
tuoba kniht ot dewolla saw eh gniht ylno ehT
.sdnal regnarts eht hguorht hcram eht gnidael
seltruT tnaiG fo dnaL eht morf elixE
.revir a fo mottob eht morf skcor eht ekil enohs selacs wen s’ekans eht elihw dniheb tfel saw
sniktA ”inohaS“ raG yb
eman dluoc eh hguoht
sniatnuom dlo esoht debmilc ylwols
.secnatsmucric fo tseb eht rednu
.deklaw yeht dnal eht ot meht decudortni ,ssendnik etinifni rieht ni
dehs saw niks rieht ot gnulc dah taht hsa eht did yeht sa dna
detsixe emoh rieht taht foorp eht llA .seltruT tnaiG fo dnaL ehT fo tfel saw ereht taht lla s’tahT
igalasT fo trap tnatropmi na
.rehtie emoh rieht ton saw siht wenk renetsiL ehT tuB
,evoc eht fo ecaep evitaler eht evael ot tnaem reven saw sihT
,nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI
.dniheb tfel eh dnal teews eht fo seirekcom elaP
morf tuo llac ot seciov dna sdrow rieht desu yehT
.retirw dna rengised emag reeuq dna suonegidni na si ohw
,tuo staob edart evif neeb dah ereht ,detrats siht lla nehW
.ees dluoc seye eht sa raf sa neerg radec eltneG
pots t’ndluoc yeht gnihtemos yb deyortsed neeb dah dna
.edam saw eonac eht nehw derebmemer roliaS ehT
fi derednow relevarT ehT
,eb llits dluow yeht
doolb dna hsa htiw nooram deniats erew relevarT ehT fo stnirptoof ehT
erew taht esoht erehW
dluoW ?yako eb yeht dluoW .detceffa erew yeht nehw retaw peed eht no tuo neeb evah dluow yehT
taht sgniht elttil eht llA
.deraperpnu ton saw eh
.sevaw deppit-maof neerg eht gnoma dekcilf erew yeht sa spihs rehto eht no hctaw peek ot gniyrt
,war tlef teef s’relevarT ehT
.oga gnol thgin taht sevaw eht htaeneb tsol eh thguoht dah eh lortnoc eht dnuof dah eh dna
.dewollof sduolc ehT
laog elbissopmi na ekil tlef
.emas eht eb reve dluow seltrut tnaig dna taerg fo dnal eht fi derednow roliaS ehT
dluoc yeht sa sklof ynam sa derehtag dna
dna wenk eh lla saw tI
sgniht llams eht revo rehto hcae gnisaet dna steb teiuQ
.meht dnuof dah sduolc eht yllautnevE
.ereht dnuof eb ot kcul doog on saw ereht tuB
wonk t’ndid eh sgniht eht rof dehca eh tub
rehtegot eta dna decnad yehT
,dedeen yeht teiuq eht meht evag yehT
.rehtona ro yaw eno
.pets txen eht saw
,koot seonac neves esoht seman eht erew esehT .idowinA ,auqsistinA ,iwainA ,iwegetoginA ,ayawinA ,inohasinA ,iholiginA
eht fo dum eht rednu morf
siht ekil yenruoj a rof eonac thgir eht neve t’nsaw sihT
.mih htaeneb ekaw eht htiw ytilaer otni kcab mih gnihsarc dna maerd evissap sih fo tuo mih gnippans
.pirt taht no deneppah gnihtemoS
.sretsiS eviF htiw retlehs dnuof dah yeht tuB
.taht etarbelec dluow yeht dnA
.revol sih fo ydob eht rof gnikool
degavlas eb dluoc sgniht suoicerp tahw revocer stnua sih pleh ot trid kcalb eht hguorht gniwalc ylraelc derebmemer eH
,tlef eugnot rieht no sdrow eht reivaeh eht ,devom yeht erom ehT
.tnepres taerg a fo taht ekil
.hguorht gninnur doohdlihc sih tneps eh tserof eht nwod denrub taht srebme eht htiw gnirekcilf
.samup dna ,reed ,sevlow emaceb yehT
.tnaem ti tahw sa tnatropmi sa t’nsaw yhW
esoht ,erofeb neeb dah spihsnoitaler rieht tahw rettam oN
.yletamitni erom elttil a mih htiw deirrac eh ssenwolloh eht
.yenruoj taht edam taht elpoep laer eht fo
.gnitniap tcartsba na htiw dluow uoy ekil eseht
tib dna desruc dna dehsang sduolc eht sa neve dna
,teiuq fo doirep a neeb dah erehT .reggib fi
eciuj eht fo noitcafsitas ehT ?hsif a hctac ot woH
.kcab derettab sih no deirrac eh skcap tnet eht sa yvaeh erew meht htiw regnol on esoht fo smaerd eht semitemoS
.tfel saw ereht lla saw tahT .seonac neveS
.thguorb yeht esruc eht gniwonk rof retteb mih edam taht gnihtemoS
…em ot dlot saw ti sa yrots siht llet I
tiurf teews-trat eht fo etsat eht rof gnignol ehT
.niks sti dehs ekans eht was eh erehW
fo emos fo snoisserpmi eht erutpac ot tpmetta na si
.dlob dna ecreif ,sdeer eht neewteb hsifwarc eht tem yeht ,tsew eht oT
.erofeb naht erom tib a fi
toos dna tlas fo stnirptoof dniheb gnivael
,wenk reven yeht elpoep yb htrae eht otni nrow setuor edart dlo eht dewollof yehT
.deifinu erom gnihtemos otni seimene dna slavir dlo ,ylimaf ,sdneirf gnitaniclac
sdrawno derats sredle nrets ,nerdlihc rieht detrofmoc srehtoM
meht htiw was eh seidob eht
.ereht tog yeht woh dna
,seltrut tnaig fo dnal a morf emac roliaS ehT
.sdoog rieht dekwah sadacic dna sdnuom eht neewteb ylthgin dehcram stirips erehw ,neerg dna
.noisiv elbuod yzah a dnoyeb ees ot drah ti edam dna seye sih gnuts tI
.yrrac ot tnaem reven erew yeht syaw ni sdnuos eht gnitsiwt ,krad eht
.sten gnihsif gnillup morf elcsum sih ni
.htaerb a nI .deneppah ti nehw ,duol oS .tsaf os neeb lla dah tI
.gnitsaob dna sekoj neewteb rehtegot edam yeht gnihtemos saw tI
.nruter reven dluoc eh taht saw
.emit ni ti ekam dluoc reveohw ,sdneirf ,ylimaF
?aes eht fo edis eltneg eht wonk yeht dluoW
.gnis sniatnuom esoht draeh eh erehw ot kcaB
.sevlesmeht sa tsixe dluoc elpoep sih erehw ecalp a ni
desiurb dna derettab tniah etihw A
.tis ot ecalp on dna teef gnihca fo derit saw eH
sa laer sa dehca eH
.yromem teews a naht rehto
.hturt elbatummi na saw taht dna
.srats emas eht rednu ereht tuo eb llits thgim taht srehto eht
.erom ecno sdnah sih ni dloh dluoc eh dehsiw eh
.denruter eb dluow spihsnoitaler eseht otni tup uoy krow dna erac taht
,tem yeht elpoep esehT
.sesuoh rieht neewteb seert eht morf ti edam dah revoL siH
.drawrof dna thgirpu meht gnipeek no sucof ot dah eH
.detfihs eltrut eht retfa emac tahw saw
mih detrofmoc rehtom sih woh derebmemer eH
drawrof gnihsup tpek eh sa mih tsniaga delggurts dna denrub ydob siH .wen enoemos ro slessev emas eht erew was eh staob eht fo slluh der detniap eht fi gnillet fo yaw on dah eH
,erom on relevarT ehT eb dluow eh dne s’thgin yB
,snoitaler ruoy ot ytilibisnopser eht ,derac taht rehtom A
nwo rieht no thgiew hcum ti htiw yrrac ot mees t’ndid
,nrob saw efil wen ,dessap dah sredlE
.kcurts dah retsasid eht nehw tuo neeb dah taht
,rednu delias dah elpoep sih seno emas eht
.tsol gniht rehtona eb dluow eh
neeb dna deid dah
.snrub gnidlacs gnihca tsuJ
.ecneirepxe nwonknu na t’nsaw ekauqhtrae na tuB
?emoh rieht ot deneppah tahw was yeht nehw kniht yeht dluow tahW
no nus gninrub sti
emoh rieht ton saw sihT
,relevart wollef ruoy
.nwo sih ot htgnerts sih dda
.oot mih morf nekat dah sduolc eht sgniht esoht fo eno neeb dah taht ekil tlef dah eH
.worromot dna yadot no desucof eh oS
.sevlesmeht sdniw gnilriwt eht dna ,sraeb ,snevar eht emaceb yehT
sriaper eht tuoba erom derac dah eh dehsiw eH .tsaf dleh eh oS
.rehtegot eonac eht ni
.snoitaler wen dliub tub ,sniatnuom eseht reuqnoc ton dluow yehT
.emoctuo esrow eht eb dluow tahw flesmih rof ediced
.noziroh tnatsid eht no meht morf
,remmus yreve fo kaep eht ta
dnal ot meht detcennoc taht sgniht eseht saw tI .emoh pu edam
srats ehT ?emoh dnif ot elba eb yeht dluoW
,rekaeps egaugnal a morf
evitcepsrep eht redisnoc ot uoy sksa ti sa
.eb reven dluoc taht
.eman a revo deugra yeht sa yad txen eht sdnah s’revoL siH fo tuo sretnilps gnillup derebmemer eH
.edis ruoy ta elpoep dah uoy sa gnol sa
deppils tahw mialcer dna
.semoh rieht morf yawa dnal eht rof neeb dah yeht deraperpnu woh
.railimaf erom ,hserf erom erew
renetsiL ehT emaceb relevarT ehT
ti woH .shtnom remmus eht ni elbatrofmocnu oot tlef taht ydob mraw oot lla ehT
dna mraw roliaS ehT peek mih leef oT
.os ti ekam dluow eh esuaceb
.dessap dna no devom dah taht esoht rof gnas yehT
.yrrac yeht snoitome eht dna selballys eht gnitsat
,did I staeb evitarran eht gnidda ni sepoh yM
.eciohc rieht ni evisiced tub tca ot wols
?retsasid siht fo tsrow eht morf tuo edih ot elba
ecalp rieht ni demrof wen gnihtemoS .sevaw esoht ni yawa dehsaw
,floWcaM boR si sihT
rof epoh dna srehto eht wollof saw od dluoc eh llA
.ereht eb ot wenk yeht htron eht
lla meht ezispac ot denetaerht taht evaw rehtona hguorht
ytirailimaf fo noitingocer elpmis a ro ytilibisnopser derahs fo
yrots eht fo sekortshsurb dna sroloc dlob eht era yehT
gnihtyreve ot kcuts taht
fo tib a fo gnilleter msilaer lacigam a si sihT
,ytiuqitnA fo ygolohtnA ni
.tae ot seirreb tnereffid dnA .gnis ot sgnos wen dnif dluow yehT
.gnivom tpek eh oS
,niaga mih dnuof dah yeht nehw dnA
ees dluoc eh hgih no ecalp sih morF
derednow mih fo trap lanoitarri rettib emoS
morf emoc dah yeht erehw tuoba seirots rieht llet dluoc smrof deirav rieht lla ni noitan sih fo snalc neves eht sa gnol sA
ti tub ,meht dnuora stirips eht fo ksa ot hcum toN
.railimaf erew snoitome eht tub tliub yeht pihsnoitaler eht ebircsed ot sdrow wen desu yehT
hcamots sih rednu morf tuo deppord gnihtemoS
elots yeht lla fo senob eht no detsaef yehT
erehw sdnalssarg nedlog eht hguorht elpoep sih del eH
.meht htiw llits erew taht esoht rof selttar dna slleb htiw decnad yehT
,swaj lufrewop htiw srotagilla eht ,tsae eht oT
.meht dnif ot elba neeb ton dah sduolc eht ,elihw a roF
.ecalper reven dluoc eh sgniht fo mih edisni eloh eht roF
.edart dluow yeht ssendas eht yb gnigduj sih ni raelc sa tsuj
,sduolc eht fo raef rof ,dehcram eh sa ecaf sih ssorc ti tel reven eH
.emoh saw sdaeh rieht detser yeht erehwon tuB
semoh rieht hguorht evord senacirruh sa sniatnuom eht no hgih tuo gnidih dna sliart dlo eht pu nekat gnieb derebmemer eH
,tfel saw taht emoh sih fo lla dleh eonac sihT
,seye rieht ees dluoc eH
ehca ehT .dnalsi eht wonk syawla dluow ydob sih fo traP
,enicidem doog deirrac stnalp hcihw thguat erew yehT
t’ndluoc eh dna ssem mirg eht gnoma dnif ot detcepxe eh tahw wonk t’ndid eH
.sffilc neddus dna sepols eltneg eht demrof enots wolley dna htrae deR
meht dewo llits eh demialc yehT
,pmac fo egde eht no tsuj ,sduolc suolaej gnikohc esoht dnif ot nekawa dluow eh thgin yrevE
.htaerb yreve htiw taorht sih pu gniggolc gals gninrub taht leef t’ndid eH .tser ,elihw a rof ,dluoc yehT
toos dna hsa dna ekoms tips niatnuom ehT
.senob dna seidob desiurb s’teelf eht rof hguone mlac saw taht dna ,retaw wols dna ssarg llat fo edam dnalhsram A
.rehtegot meht peek ot dah eH
,morf dliuber dluoc uoy sgniht fo tros eht erew esoht tuB