.siht si meht fo mottob eht ta tub
.htolc elohw morf tliub ,ekopseB
sregnif neewteb debbuR     krab enip
.ytitnedi esraoc morf war sdnah htiW erauqs dna riaf flesym tliub I
,yad htnet yreve gnippikS
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,erutlucbus elohw eht ,ytinummoc yrruf ehT
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.noitinifed-fles ni esicrexe gnolefil a no desab si
desserp dna dedaenk I
,evruc yreve gnirovaS ,dezeeuqs dna
thgir eht no dednuof era sthgir +QTBGL lla dnA
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb meop a
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,evol I ohw ediced yam ydobon taht
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,regguR .P.B yb daeR  .em tub
.nooM-ooM elbaffeni eht
,regguR .P.B yb uoy rof daer
”erauqs dna riaF“  yojne esaelP
,thgir tlef lla ti litnU
skoob dna ,smeop ,seirots dnif nac uoy erehw ,kni.oykam ta elbaliava si gnitirw reH
.cisum ruoy htiw emit nI     evom srepiw dleihsdniw eht nehw rO
;erauqs dna riaf eman ym thguob I
swap gniyrruh rednU     sevael elpam fo repsihw eht rO
rehto hcae htiw pu eniL     seert owt ni sehcnarb taht yaw tcefrep eht gnidnif rO
.uargnegiE noitcelloc reh morf si meop s’yadoT
fo llems teews eht ekiL
,J yreve gnirovaS ,niaga dna
.reh fo tseb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
”regit a ma I“ yas eW
.enilno eerf rof daer ro esahcrup ot
,snosaer fo rebmun yna rof ytinummoc yrruf eht ot nward era seititnedi reeuq dna elpoep reeuQ
,noitinifed-fles ot
wodniw eht hguorhT     llaf wons eht gnihctaw dna edisni gnittis ekiL
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,thgir tlef ti litnU ,elttit htfif yreve gnippikS
ykcits ydaerlA     sdub wen fo
niaga ti etorw I
palrevo tcefrep eht rO
”erauqs dna riaF“ saw sihT    .pas htiw
.ti tpecca sdneirf ruo dna ”god a ma I“ ro
.nooM-ooM elbaffeni eht
,ma I tahw ,ma I ohw
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
”regdab a ma I“ ro