.dehcaorppa semaJ nehw eye na tab t’ndid
,sthguoht sih ni decar smaercs deohcE
,dnim sih ni tuo deyalp ysatnaf deregnil A
noitidnoc lacidem suoires a fo tneilc a mrofni ot dah eh revenehw yltnelis evresbo dna tis ot mih rof drawkwa syawla saw tI
,deliaf taht nehW
,syad wef a retfA
?gnineppah siht si yhW !kcuf hO !doG hO“
.niaga uoy ees dluow I thguoht reven I“
,tnemeganam naht rehto ,ereh esle enoyreve dnA
.ytitnedi sih erucsbo ot sedahs krad raew dluow dna
.moor rekcol eht edisni
taog enipla yerg eht ezingocer dluoc dnim thgir rieht ni eno oN
,riahc sih otni delttes ylluf semaJ erofeb hguohT
sknaht laiceps a ,oslA
enam etihw gniwolf gnol ylsuomrone na htiw
dedeen eb dluow secivres sih yhw dnatsrednu dluoc semaJ
ytinummoc faed eht ni enoyna dneirfeb ylpeed ro etad reven ot saw
sgniht fo stros eseht tuoba tuhs shtuom ruo peek ot dellepmoc yllagel era I dna ycnega eht os ,ycerces ot nrows m’I ,enif s’tI“
ehcatsum rabeldnah yerg egral a dah retto dekcats trohs ehT
.noitacol eht tuo kcehc ot nalp a delipmoc semaJ
,ni emac rotcod retto nworb trohs eht ecnO
.devlovni sksir evah dluow ereh uoy gniteem taht teg I
.tnemom a rof seye dekcol owt eht sa
”!siht ekil gig tnatropmi na rof tuo ruetama na dnes t’ndluow ycnega eht ,emit tsrif ym t’nsi siht yrrow t’nod dnA
.teiuq ylegnarts saw taht retnec eht ni eno saw ereht hguohT
.redistuo na sa mih delangis
.derekcins noillats ehT
.hteet sih hcnelc yltnelis noxiD dehctaw eh sa yllanretni degnirc dna egassem lluf eht deyevnoc eh ,llitS
”,esoht raew dluow esnes noihsaf tneced htiw nosrep enas oN
.emoh ta repeeb krow ym tfel I derebmemer tsuj I tub ,yrros m’I“
ytinummoc faed eht nihtiw elpoep tsoM
.rebmun enohp a mih gnivig eb dluow noxiD yhw ot sa dexelprep saw taog enipla ehT
enola semaJ dna noxiD tfel ylpmis dna euc rieht koot owt ehT
rood eht tuo debmilc yltfiws eh
.reilrae llaf taht morf ehcadaeh a tog I ,sulP
”.niaga rehto hcae ees neve t’now ylbaborP
”!uoy rof eno edivorp esrun a evah nac I ,sevitanretla xes efas gnirolpxe no stelhpmap yna deen uoy fI
”.rebmemer ot em rof reisae ti sekaM
.ecaf sih nwod sdaeb taews fo sloop
.tisiv s’yadot rof sevlesmeht deraperp lla yeht sa klat llams edam eerht ehT
”!ereh uoy htiw nees eb t’nac I yhw s’tI
.lrig ruoy ot deneppah tahw tuoba yrros ,yeH“
”?emit rehtona ecalp etavirp erom a ta rehto hcae wonk ot teg nac ew ebyaM
snairtsedep rehto eht htiw ni dednelb eH
.spil daer ot noxiD rof tluciffid ti edam hcihw ,pil reppu sih derevoc taht
,myg lausac a fo scitehtsea eht dah ti hguohT
,yrrow t’nod dnA !emosewA“
.tneilc sih teem dluoc eh os
.muisanmyg lausac a naht tnereffid on dekool edisni eht
.keew rehtona rof detaert dna
.laed gib a t’nia ti os ycerces ot nrows er’uoy ,dias uoy ekil …yawynA
.flesym nialpxe ot tnemeganam yb ni dellac saw I“
,delkcuhc smailliW .rD
,nwod flesmih mlac ot deirt eh sa
,goDdliWD2@ ,rettiwt no mih wollof nac uoY
!taob emas eht ni era eW
.emoh daeh ot deen od yllaer I …tub ot ekil d'I“
krow fo sraey owt retfa ngis eman a fo kcal sih taht tnematset a saw tI
?ereh noxiD si yhW
.suomynona gniniamer elihw ytilauxes sih erolpxe dluoc eh hcihw ni syaw tuo erugif ot deirt semaJ ,yhw si tahT
.tsirw sih ot detniop noxiD
noillats eht ot ti dednah eH
tsuj I t’nac yhW
.dnatsrednu t’ndluow yeht esuaceb sdneirf faed ym htiw siht tuoba klat t’ndluoc I
gnol a taog enipla eht evig ot revo dehcaer eh ,daetsnI
.tnemngissa hguone ysae na eb ot demees tnemtnioppa eht sa feiler fo hgis a koot semaJ
syawllah eht denroda
,snrut wef a retfA
.taht ekil gnihtemos htiw evil ot noxiD rof ekil neeb evah tsum ti tahw deredisnoc ylsuoires reven eH
egelivirp a hcus detnarg eb dluow eh denigami reven eh ,ycnega eht ni krow fo sraey owt sih lla nI
;demaercs eciov daeh s’semaJ
.ytic eht otni repeed ruoted a ekat ot decrof saw eh dna
pil rewol sih tib semaJ
.tneilc eht ot seihtapmys sih yevnoc ot
.terces a tnemtnioppa s’rotcod ym tpek uoY
revo dehcaer noxiD
.ssenlli suoires a ro recnac lanimret dah yeht tneilc sih llet ot saw
.drawkwa erom yna noisses eht fo dne eht ekam ton ot woh
.tneilc sih saw noillats eht taht
,strats eslaf wef a retfA
.rehtona eno htiw tcatnoc esolc gnipeek owt htiw
”?tnilps a dedeen regnif gnir ruoy
.pots mih ekam ot ecaf sih dehcnup dna ffo mih dekcub I …oS
”!niaga rotcod eht tisiv ot gnivah fo smret ni naem I
.tnemngissa s’yadot fo seton eht revo weiver ylkciuq ot
.sgniht kcoms kcalb esoht raew sreterpretni uoy llA“
.noxiD ekil elpoep wonk ot gnitteg dnim t’ndluow eH
,worbeye na sesiar semaJ
,setunim wef a retfA
.tnih yvaeh a evag tnorf tuo eletneilc dna ngis eht tub elbakramernu dekool flesti gnidliub ehT
,pots derised eht edam sub eht ecnO .pu gnihcnelc
,riahc sih ni edis ot edis morf dekcilf liat sih sa gnola deddon noillats ehT
.em no detaehc dneirflrig ym tuo dnuof I retfa stset esoht teg ot dedeen tsuJ
dedivorp lla erew oitap foor a dna ,sretaeht roodni llams ,smoor rekcol
.edistuo ylluf ecno nus noonretfa eht fo ecarbme mraw eht htiw tem erew semaJ dna noxiD
”?ereh gnimoc neeb uoy evah gnol woH
!uoy teem ot ecin saw ti …yawynA
.delims dna noillats dekan eht ot denrut neht eH
!fo erac ekat ot evah I sklof gnuoy eht fo tsom ekilnu daorb yreve gnikcuf dnuora og ylpmis t’nod uoY
,sexes emas eht fo eno gnola tel
.nep dna dapeton reterpretni sih eveirter ot xob evolg eht denepo ylkciuq semaJ
.noxiD ot noitamrofni eht deyaler dna
.mih ot txen noihsuc hcuoc eht derevoc yletelpmoc taht sriah liat dna
.sfeirb sih ot nwod saw eh nehw suovren ylemertxe saw eh ,dlot eb hturT
DI dna tnemyap rof deksa ylpmis flow ehT
.elihw a rof rehtona eno ssorca emoc t’now ylbaborp yeht
.ycnega eht ot nruter ot ruoh na tuoba dah eh was dna
.emoh evord eh sa srae sih tuohguorht dehsur doolb sih
neddih saw gnidliub ehT
.pu desnet ydob sih tey
.yawa skcolb wef a esuohhtab eht sdrawot dedaeh dna
,detiaw owt eht sA
.enot dna emulov rewol a ni ekops retto eht sa
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tixe eht rof detpo dnah rehto eht no semaJ
.nageb ew erofeb no ti tup mih dah dna modnoc a mih evag I
.skcabward yna dehgiewtuo ylevissam
slirtson s’semaJ fo tuo dehsur ria toH  .deksa noxiD
!nwod kool I did kcuf eht yhW“
”?su neewteb siht peek
”?repap fo eceip a ro koobeton a evah uoy oD
”.ereh ot klat ot esle enoyna dah yllaer reven I“
.muminim ruoh-owt eht rof detnuoc yap sih taht ykcul flesmih deredisnoc semaJ
detaluceps semaJ
”!ereh yats t’nac I …tub toh os s’eH
detnaw eh gniht tsaL
.euqisyhp ralucsum sih fo stcepsa redaorb eht deniltuo hcihw
,ngis ot pu sdnah sih thguorb dna
.enizagam yssolg a daer ohw
.detcetorpnu em kcuf ot deirt eh dna ffo modnoc eht edils mih tlef I setunim wef a retfa …tuB
.reterpretni remrof sih ees ot kcaba nekat saw noxiD
swen eht morf kcaba nekat saw semaJ
!metsys ruoy ni silihpyS ro ,VIH ,sititapeH ,aidymalhC fo sngis on era ereht ,stset eniru dna doolb ruoy gninrecnoc woN“
,dias noxiD ekil ,sseldrageR
llams a tuo tel noxiD
dleh llits taht sdneirf doohdlihc sih fo wef a llacer dluoc semaJ
.dengis noxiD ”?JJ ,yako uoY“
,evres ot tneilc rehtona tsuj t’nsaw noxiD
.tnemyolpme gnitcelloc flesmih ees noos dluoc eh dna efil lanosrep s'semaJ tuoba pils eno tsuJ
.hcum em htiw klat yllaer t’nod yeht …tuB
wolley rof ngis eht deifidom dah noxiD
?eman lluf ruoy s’tahw ,oS
.deneppah tahw meht llet dluoc I os repap dna nep a em evig ot dah yeht ,esruoC
.redluohs tfel sih no detser lewot a elihw dekan nwod deppirts dah eH
.terces elttil rieht eb lliw ti
.stneilc rieht fo srettam lanosrep ni devlovni gnitteg morf dedaussid erew yehT .snotamotua
.krowtra denoissimmoc dna stcejorp gnitirw erutuf rof
dne na ot emac yadkrow eht sa
.tniap etihw dna kcalb fo enot gnihsalc a detcelfer ruf ehT
.ssentif lacisyhp fo euqisyhp elam fo murtceps a detcelfer epyt ydob riehT
,snoitacifiralc yralubacov dna stsilkcehc latnem wef a retfA
,deddon noxiD  ”.yawyna tey toN
.liated tcefrep erutcip ni ydob dekan ralucsum
tnemtnioppa eht ot ylrae setunim 51 evirra ot erudecorp dradnats saw ti ,semaJ roF
.tnemtnioppa eht tuoba laed gib a gnikam ton rof sknahT“
.em detcefni evah thgim elohssa eht taht deirrow saw I …llitS
”.kcolc eht revo er’uoy nehw ygnits teg ot dnet yeht wonk I .ycnega ruoy ot kcab teg dluohs uoY
.niaga neppah reven ll’ti
.moor eht ni snoillats eerht ees dluoc semaJ
.mih evag ycnega sih noitpircsed eht dehctam taht
,sseneros eht ehtoos ot regnif gnir thgir sih bur ot tnilps eht detfil noxiD  ”?taht s’yhW“
srae dna eson knip s’taog ehT
.trap tsal eht timo ot egru eht tlef tub
.noitcartta niam eht t’nsaw ti
.rood ybraen a yb dessap eh sa pu dekcip rae sih taht liated llams eno saw erehT
.tnemssarrabme dna kcohs htiw epaga htuom sih htiw pu derats eH
nep dna koobeton gniterpretni sih debbarg semaJ
,hsinif ot tuoba saw eh sa tsuJ
tuo erugif ot deirt semaJ sa tcatnoc eye ekorb yehT
.dnaherofeb hcnul emos pu kcip ot tnaw did eh
.reggoj yranidro na sa mih ekat tsuj dluow elpoep depoh eH
.ecnartne tol gnikrap eht rof moor ekam ot drawrof delwarc eh erofeb
,yad eht fo tser eht roF
.dnuora gniog llits gniht VIH siht htiw yllaicepsE
.tnemom a rof mih pots ot redluohs tfel s’taog enipla eht deppat noxiD ,tol gnikrap eht rof dedaeh semaJ sA
,denigami eh ekil yrtneprac etarobale ro ,erutinruf suoitatnetso
.llew sa niaga uoy ssorca emoc ot yppah m’I“
.tcejbus cificeps siht terpretni ot deen eht etapicitna t’ndid eh sa
.esnecil s’revird sih dna
,sesuohhtab esoht fo eno saw ti taht
htiw tneilc a rof terpretni ot gnivah fo ksir eht ta semaJ tup dluow os od oT
.skcottub evissam sih neewteb gnuh taht elat esroh etihw yffulf detagnole na htiw gnola
.noos niaga tuo gnah ot ekil uoy fi rebmun siht htiw em tcatnoc nac uoy ,ereH“
,deunitnoc neht eH
erom gnihton erew semaJ ekil elpoep taht tniop eht emoh deremmah ycnega ehT
.tsiaw rieht dnuora slewot htiw
teef devooh sih rednu delevart selbmur thgilS
,ecnalg peed a derahs yehT
kniw thgils a evag noxiD
"retnuocnE railimaF“
.meht tsgnoma doots ohw noillats boc hsirI elam etihw dna kcalb A
.thguoht tsrif eh naht nommoc ni sgniht erom
.mih otni ydob sih dnirg dna sserp yltfos noillats dekan eht tlef eh sa ecalp ni ezorf semaJ .guh etamitni
.uoy rof tol a neeb evah thgim siht wonk I
.gnineppah saw tahw htiw esnes ekam ot deirt dnim dexelprep sih sa dedaehthgil emaceb semaJ
kcab dengis semaJ
,izzucaj eht ot yaw sih edam eh ecno spahreP
”.ruoh na rednu ni enod eb dluohS
,rettiwt no lsaflowekaw@ ot
morf meht tneverp ot sgel dna sdnah sih tuo hcterts ot dah eh ,llitS
s’noxiD fo espmilg retteb a thguac eH
suiraD fo dneirf a
.noxiD ot pu dekool semaJ
.ksed tnorf eht dehcaorppa dna esuohhtab eht fo tnorf ni devirra semaJ
.ycilop a hcus ot sedisnwod erew ereht teY
.noos emityna ycnega eht deen dluow noxiD fi gnillet on saw ereht
koob enohp sih nepo dna emoh teg ot dedeen eh ,tahw rettam oN
.ffo ti yalp ot deirt semaJ
,ytic renni eht ni noitalupop faed elbazis a htiW
.rehtona eno rof serised rieht htiw elbatrofmoc dna detarebil leef nac nem erehw ecalp a
ytilicaf eht morf detixe eh erofeb elttek aet a ekil dewolg srae s’semaJ fo spit ehT
,snades gnilzzug sag fo swor lareves dniheb deppots eh sA
.strapretnuoc gniraeh rieht ot derapmoc eugav eb ot elpoep fo epyt eht t’nerew yehT
.erots yrecorg a edisni elsia tuokcehc a ta dnif dluow uoy taht enO
.ereh m’I taht wonk sdneirf faed ym fo enon dnA
.sfeirb thgit erow taht
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,mih ot txen tas semaJ
,gnieb emit eht roF
.izzucaj eht sdrawot sriatsnwod dedaeh eh sa redluohs sih revo lewot eht deirrac dna
.rac sih otni taerter ot deirt eh sa
”?pu uoy kcip ot enoemos rof gnitiaw uoy erA
.tifeneb etaidemmi na saw hcihw
.wodniw edis s’revird eht tuo daeh sih htiw delley semaJ
.smoor rekcol eht rof dedaeh dna
.ecaf sih no noisserpxe deworruf a dah noillats eht sa
.dias smailliW .rD
.reterpretni na gnidneirfeb yb smron gnikaerb tuoba seirrow eht edirrevo dluow enoemos htiw tcennoc ot deen eht woh ees dluoc semaJ
.regnif gnir thgir sih no nrow tnilps elbaeciton a dah noillats ehT
.JJ uoy llac I tuoba woH …thgirlA“
.mih gnidnif dneirf ro ,eugaelloc krow
,sivaD suiraD yb ”retnuocnE railimaF“ saw sihT
,sizzucaj ,sloop ,sanuas fo yarra nA
.myg eht ot daeh ylbaborp ll’I hguohT .noitatropsnart cilbup ekat I ,epoN“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
mih no denwad tI
,hsac emos ,lewot a ,spolf pilf
xobevolg eht ni yawa koobeton gniterpretni eht tup eh
.eritta mrofinu fo eciohc rieht rof sreterpretni rieht ta nuf ekop ot stneilc rof nommoc saw ti dnA
,deergA“ ,deddon semaJ
.ecalp eht tuoba noitamrofni erom pu kool ot
.sriatspu smoor rekcol eht sdrawot yaw sih edam semaJ sa
.mih no denwad noitautis eht fo thgiew eht sa
,hguone riaF“ ,delkcuhc noxiD
,srood tnorf eht ni dezzub ecnO
.noitartsurf htiw deffuh noxiD
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
!yllanoisseforp gniterpretni morf derrab dna esnecil ym fo deppirts eb ll’I
.hteet sih dehcnelc ylthgit eh
”?dekoops uoy tog s’tahW
,ytilicaf eht tfel semaJ erofeB
?pu s’tahw ,em llet ,oS
.tuo reets eht dekcik dna yrots eht fo edis ym deveileb yeht ,sraey rof em nwonk ev’yeht esuaceB
.deterpretni semaJ elihw ekops eh erofeb ti deweiver ylluferac dna
meht dezilanoitasnes
raelc saw ti sa flesmih ot delkcuhc taog enipla ehT
.loretselohc ro ,noitcnuf revil ,slevel ragus doolb fo senil eht gnola gnihtemos detcepxe eH
moor eht fo edis eno nO
.mih no taehc lrig a evah reve dluow noxiD ekil noillats gnorts emosdnah a yhw ot sa
,nrut eht edam dna sag eht otno desserp ylkciuq semaJ
,daeh sih koohs semaJ  .sksa noxiD
.meht tops depleh I ecnis ni em nekat ev’yehT
.ti ot esle hcum gnihtoN
snoitasrevnoc lausac htiw dezzub sllah ehT
.kcuts tas ,snroh sih eerf ot elbanu ,semaJ
.tfel ydaerla dah tnorf ni srac eht sa
tiaw ot mih denoitom dna revo deklaw noxiD
.elbatrofmoc teg ot em rof cilbup oot sleef tsuj ti …tuB !od I
.llew sa uoy teem ot ecin yllaer saw ti
.saw noillats eht ohw dezilaer eh sa renroc eht otni dekcab semaJ
.gnidliub etihw llat suoucipsnocni na edistuo ngis ycnaf a fo thgis eht thguac eye s’semaJ
,seye sih fo renroc eht morF
.fo eton koot semaJ taht ytilicaf eht yb
a rof noillats eht gnikatsim flesmih ees dluoc semaJ
.teef sih detfihs noxiD
.snoisiced htaed dna efil detatcid taht
.yhtapme htiw pu dekool seye sih sa
.etartnecnoc ot deirt eh sa
.erutluc yag dna erutluc faed
,yawa dehsaw tnemssarrabme fo tnemom taht retfA
,senihcam egaugnal naht
.xaler meht ekam ot sdnah sih koohs eh sa detartsurf ylbisiv dekool noxiD
.gnitirwdnah s’noxiD derimda dna
,noitcasnart eht retfA
,robhgien a fo ytilibissop wol eht evah dluow
.oga shtnom wef a tsuj
.saib dna tnemegduj sih repmah dluow hcihw
!kciuq tuo dna ni gniog
”?ngis eman ruoy s’tahw ,yaw eht yB“
draob pilc a tuo thguorb rotcod retto eht ,noitaulave eht retfA
,snoitadnemmocer htlaeh dna tset eht retfA
!mih fo leurc yllufwa saw tahT
emac yad eht nehw hguohT
.wonk uoy nem yag faed rehto eb tsum ereht erus m’I  ,sulP
,teef sih delffuhs semaJ
.level lanosrep repeed a no mih wonk dluoc taht elpoep wef os ylno era ereht ,esroh emosdnah
.eb thgim tneilc sih erehw tuo dnif ot
.traeh sih dehcnelc daerd fo esnes a sa pil rewol sih tib semaJ
”?reterpretni eht uoy erA“
,elims a dehsalf noxiD
.sehtolc teerts rieht morf nwod pirts ot detrats yeht sa
.llawyrd eht morf tuo snroh eht deirp ylluferac smra gnorts sih sa
.spih s’noxiD revo detser smra sih sa
.yad eht ni reilrae stnemeveihca gnitfilthgiew tnecer rieht tuoba detsaob owt ehT
.em erongi uoy gnittel ton m’I os em dnatsrednu nac taht ereh eno ylno eht er’uoY“
.mih tuoba railimaf yletaidemmi gnihtemos saw ereht
.ecnartne eht sdrawot deklaw tsaf dna
.edisni egdol ot snroh sih desuac hcihw llawyrd eht otni dehsams daeh sih fo kcab ehT
,repeeb krow sih dniheb evael dluow eH
”!niaga uoy gniees ecin si ti ,eil t’now I …tuB
.trops ’lo seirrow on ,lleW“
,sngis s’noillats eht deciov semaJ retfA
esroh boc hsirI emosdnah yldettimda na saw edis rehto eht nO
noitasnes gninrub tfos A
,reffo ot uoy fo teews s’tI“
ereht mih tops dluow semaJ ot esolc enoyna taht noitacidni elttil saw erehT
,yenruoj eht ni raf siht emoc ot deganam dah eH
rotcod eht dna noxiD erehw noitisop a ni tis ot erus edam semaJ
flesmih esopmoc ot sdnah sih tuo koohs ylkciuq semaJ ,sseldrageR
.tneilc a naht erom gnihton saw boc hsirI eht ,yadot tuB
.htob ni etapicitrap ylluf t’ndluoc noillats eht ,teY
dnim s’taog enipla eht deugalp ehcadaeh gnislup A
ytilaer otni kcab flesmih deppans yllanif semaJ
,dehsinif saw tnemtnioppa eht elihW
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa laugnilib reeuq kcalb a ,sivaD suiraD yb
ni meht dellac esrun kle eht
.noillats redlo gnipparts a morf
,rekcol sih sdrawot dedaeh dna yawa dekcab ylkciuq semaJ
.riahc sih ni kcab dial noxiD
.stset doolb gnimocpu tuoba meht dlot stneilc remrof nehw rof depperp eh tahw saw taht tsael tA
.teef devooh sih no pu mih depleh dna
”!seno retrams eht fo eno er’uoy ,nam faed a roF
noxiD ot revo dekool yltnatculer semaJ
.sesseug dnoces htiw dellif ylwols dnim s’semaJ
.yrots siht rof tnatlusnoc evitaerc faed a sa detca ohw
.sdeen dna stnaw lanoitome htiw nosrep a tub
.tneilc a morf ngis eman a eviecer ot mih rof ronoh eguh a saw tI
.kcab stset doolb emos gnitteg dna pu kcehc raluger a tsuj rof ereh m’I
.ytic eht edistuo devil ohw esoht ot derapmoc tcelaid nabru na detcelfer elyts gningis s’noillats ehT
.neerg denrut thgil eht erofeb
,ngis ot pu sdnah sih thguorb noxiD
tfel eht no noillats ehT
snroh s’semaJ morf llawyrd fo stib eht ffo detsud neht eH
hguoht semaJ ot denrut saw kcab siH
,daeh sih detlit semaJ
”?taht retfa deneppah tahW
edistuo detiaw sllub ylrub egral wef A
.ylthgit noxiD otno dleh eh elihw mriuqs taog enipla eht edam hcihw
.siht raew I taht ycilop ynapmoc s'ti tub wonk I“
.emoh yaw sih edam dna
.semoceb ciffart eht dab woh rettam on
.ytinummoc faed eht nihtiw snoitcennoc ynam depoleved t’ndah semaJ
tsuj era ew ,yregrus traeh-nepo on s’tI
,nettalf srae s’noxiD
.tsoob ecnedifnoc fles a flesmih evig ot
.sgnignoleb sih eveirter ot deirt eh sa yek rekcol eht htiw detegdif sdnah ykahs s'semaJ
.ereh er’ew taht wonk ot sdeen ydobon tuB
skeehc s’semaJ fo sedis eht pu delkcirt
stnemtrapa emocni-wol dna sexelpmoc eciffo llat lareves dniheb
,serutluc owt neewteb deppart saw noxiD
.ekil erew secalp pukooh eseht tahw tuoba ofni elttil saw erehT
.sruoh gnitarepo sti htiw gnola
.oga skeew wef a yug reets a htiw ecneirepxe xes dab a dah I ...lleW“
,snoitasrevnoc strops
.taht ekil laed war a dah ohw syug wef a wonk I
peed poleved ot sreterpretni rof neddibrof saw tI
elur tsrif ehT
.eno evah t’nod …I“
.llaw eht tsniaga demmals dna sdrawkcab delbmuts eH
,uoy ot ti kaerb ot etaH“
,ytilicaf eht ot esolc detautis taht etuor sub a ekat
.nosnhoJ semaJ m’I“
dluow selcitra repapswen lacol dna lanoitan eht fo tsoM
.htlaeh nwo ruoy rof ytilibisnopser gnikat tsuj erew uoy ,dnatsrednu I
,yrotagored eb ot tnaem t’nerew snoitnetni s’smailliW .rD taht dootsrednu eH
eletneilc eht fo snoitasrevnoc edis draeh srae yppolf siH
,yllanoisseforp noxiD rof terpretni ot elba eb reven yam eh fi nevE
.saw etteuqite reporp eht tahw yltcaxe wonk t’ndid eH
moor rekcol eht otni klaw ot deneppah nem wef A
”.regnif gnir ym rof tnilps a teg ot dah I yhw dnA
.seirots trohs gnillepmoc etaerc ot dnuorgkcab dna egdelwonk cimedaca sih sesu ohw
”?tnemtnioppa s’rotcod a gniod emit tsrif ruoy siht sI
.ti no dednal maeb leets a retfa tnedicca ecalpkrow a morf tsuj saw siht …mU
spih s’noxiD no-sdnah sih decalp ylthgil taog enipla ehT
.ecalp koot xes yag yzeels dna sgurd erehw smuls gniretsef nwod-nur naht erom gnihton eb ot
.ecaf sih morf deniard doolb sa elap erew
koobeton eht otno dleh ylthgit eh
,dessap emit sa hguohT
.tnemtnioppa siht tuoba detacilpmoc gnihtyna t’nia ereht tub
.rekool doog a noitnem ot ton
?siht hO“  .deksa semaJ
.ytilicaf eht otni yrtne dewolla yllanif saw semaJ
.tnemesab eht morf pu debmilc cisum ssab eht elihw
,ssik llams eht retfA
”.tuoba erew stset doolb eht tahw reilrae uoy llet ot dessarrabme oot saw I
.deksa semaJ ”?deneppah tahW“
noillats etihw dna kcalb a saw eH
,ytilauxes nwo sih htiw smret ot emoc ylluf t’ndah eh elihW
revo dekool neht boc hsirI ehT
.ni sgnignoleb sih dehsats dna
.YTT a hguorht senil enohp eht esu dluoc elpoep faed taht gnittegrof dna bmud gnileef
tsuj tI“   ”.taht ekil uoy fo egatnavda ekat ot deirt enoemos yrros m’I …ees I“
rood eht tsap deklaw tsaf eh elihw srae yppolf sih fo spit eht ot pu delkcit hsur toh A .”noegnuD ehT“
.ytilicaf eht fo smoor dna
.gnivil a rof noitcurtsnoc od I
dniheb morf deralb nroh rac a
.wonk uoy ,enoemos htiw ti tuoba klat ot doog sleef
,draobyek lacinahcem yerg reh morf pu gnikool neve tuohtiW
sserdnu ot rekcol ytpme na dnuof eH
ssalgixelp eht dniheb flow nat tesyvaeh ehT
?eman ruoy s’tahW
.yats ot uoy dewolla yeht dalg m’I“
,tneilc tsap a htiw devlovni yletamitni emoceb ot ,sediseB
noillats eht htiw dnob resolc a gniworg dna gnidneirfeb fo stifeneb eht
,sdnoces wef a retfA
.redluohs tfel s’taog enipla eht no dnah thgir sih depsalc ot
.reilrae uoy ssimsid ot gniyrt rof yrros m’I
.gnillac tuohtiw ecalp eht tuoba nrecsid dluoc eh ofni hcum ton saw ereht hguohT
.ytinummoc faed eht ni esoht htiw spihsnoitaler ro spihsdneirf
.detaerc rotcod eht noitautis drawkwa eht dootsrednu semaJ dna noxiD
”.elohssa evissergga eht saw I thguoht
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
smailliW .rD sa flesmih decudortni eh
!revo si reerac ym ,siht ekil ecalp a ni tneilc remrof a htiw tuo gnuh I wenk elpoep fI
…os epoh I“  deggurhs noxiD
.noitcetorp nwo sih rof tsuj
dednetta eh seunev eht erus ekam ot detnaw osla semaJ tuB
.ti denoitnem eh nehw tespu ylbisiv
yb gnissap rekrowoc a fo ytilibissop eht detneverp ti depoh eh sa
.egaugnal ngis dnatsrednu dluoc taht ereh esle enoyna ssorca emac reven I
.tol eht otni devrews eh erofeb seye sih dellor taog enipla nworb dna kcalb ehT
.sehtolc teerts sih otni kcab sserd ot detrats dna rebmun enohp eht detpecca eh
”!og ot deen yllaer I
”.htoot deppihc a dna eson nekorb a htiw mih tfeL
,spil s’semaJ no kcep tfos a evael ot drawrof denael noillats ehT
.regnif gnir deniarps s’noxiD no noitaulave kciuq a did osla eH
droccA adnoH revliS sih fo foor eht otno thguac snroh siH
.eritta gnihtolc dna etuor lamron sih t’nsaw siht sa
.sknaht sih evag eh sa
.elbissop sa noos sa tnemtnioppa eht dne ot thguos dna doom eht nethgil ot hgual labrev elbatrofmocnu
!evah yam uoy srentrap elam ro/dna elamef yna htiw xes efas ecitcarp ot eunitnoc uoy taht tnatropmi llits si ti ,woN
,9891 ni gninepoer sti saw esuohhtab cificeps eht tuoba elcitra repapswen tnecer ylno ehT
erahs yam owt eht woh tuoba
gninnuts a rof nevE
”?but toh eht ni em nioj dna sriatsnwod emoc ot ekil uoy dluow …oS
,esuohhtab eht ot nwod pirt sub eht ekat ot detrats eh dna
.gniog tpek eh tub pots ot mih denoitom I
”?rotcod eht ksa ot gniog uoy era tahw dnA
,yldneirf eb ot demees noillats ehT
.xaler ylluf ot elba eb ll’eh
”…nwod kool t’nod ,nwod kool t’noD !nwod kool t’noD .nwod kool ton dna yrt tsuJ
.srevol tsap rieht tsniaga segdurg gnorts
.llac ot nehw rof etad dna emit eht htiw gnola rebmun enohp sih nwod etirw ot detrats noxiD sa
.etummoc rieht no elihw
.emoh daeh ot detrats eh dna
.moor gnitiaw tseraen eht ot semaJ detniop regnif yenob gnol reh
.ssik a mih wolb noxiD was dna denrut eh
.eciffo s’rotcod eht ot txen tops a dnuof yllautneve eh sa setunim eht nwod detnuoc draobhsad sih edisni kcolc ehT
.boj ruoy tuoba deracs er’uoy taht dnatsrednu I“
dnim sih eugalp ot deunitnoc sthguohT
”!llew seog yad ruoy fo tser eht epoH
,hteet sih hguorht ria emos ni dekcus semaJ
.erusserp doolb dna ,thgieh
drib eht mih evag
.doohilevil sih mih tsoc dluoc
.ti teg I“ ,dehgual noxiD
”.uoy ot sllac enohp ekam dna eviecer ot em wolla lliw ti
,koobeton eht mih dednah noxiD
”,niaga rehto hcae ees ew epoh I“
,egdelwonk etamitni lanosrep
.noitnetta sih teg ot mih ta devaw noxiD
,tnemngissa sih rof etal eb ot tuoba ton saw eH
”.em fo deracs era ereh elpoep tsom kniht I …dnA
.rekcins llams a tuo tel dna dnah s’semaJ ta nwod dekool noxiD
.uoy rof tif doog a eb t’ndluow I tub
.noitnetta sih teg ot semaJ ta devaw noxiD
nem fo seiceps dna yteirav yrevE
.nialpxe ot deen t’nod uoY
,sroloc duol fo daetsnI
raeppa t’ndid noxiD
.droccA revils sih ot kcab deklaw tsaf eh erofeb eybdoog devaw dna euc sih koot semaJ
,emoh ta retirwepytelet a evah I
XNG kciuB eht ni revird yeknod ehT
”.em dnuora hsiffodnats neeb sah enoyreve ,neht ecnis dnA
.sdnah rieht fo htob koohs dna
noitcurtsnoc rojam yb dekcolb saw etuor lamron siH
dluoc eh sa tsaf sa sngis teerts eht fo seman eht nwod delbbircs dna dettops eH
.eciwt ngis J a ekam ot dnah sih denoitom tub ni bmuht sih tpek eh sa
.eciffo s’rotcod eht ni sevlesmeht detautis owt eht dna
.rood eht sdrawot daeh sih denoitom dna snoillats rehto owt eht ot revo dekool noxiD
ksed tnorf eht ta tsinoitpecer ssenoil delevirhs eht htiw ni dekcehc eH
namow torrap redlo na saw
.ssenedur laitnetop rof ekatsim sih pu revoc ot deirt semaJ
.elbat eeffoc sih tuohguorht derettacs seton fo lwarps a htiw hcuoc eht no tas semaJ sa dessap syad wef A
.thgirla saw eh fi semaJ deksa yllabrev dna
.ledom revoc enizagam redliubydob
.rekcol eht morf nep dna koobeton sih eveirter ot denrut dna deddon semaJ
,emoh etuor sub eht nO
”?llet uoy dluoc woH“
”?reilrae uoy htiw erew taht snoillats rehto esoht tuoba tahw tuB“
mih ot revo dekool noillats ehT
…yhw nosaer eht taht saW
,nep dna koobeton a ,gab myg llams a gnirb dluow eh ,tsom eht tA
.ecnahc a noillats eht evig tsael ta ot dellepmoc tlef llits semaJ
dellac noitces tnemesab eht morf cisum bulc eht deinapmocca snaom dna shgis fo ynohpmys A
.ngis ot mih rof ylbatrofmoc mih ees htob nac
.was eh taht edisni serutaerc rehto owt ylno erew erehT
.sriatsnwod noegnud eht ta xes gnivah erew eW“
.snoitnetni dna sdrow rieht htiw drawrof ylemertxe eb ot dednet
sexof munitalp emosdnah gnuoy owt fo thgis eht yb deteerg saw taog enipla eht
dexaler ylluf ydob s’semaJ
esuohhtab yag eht fo sserdda dna eman esicerp eht delaever koobenohp ehT
”!ssa ruoy evoM“  sivaD suiraD yb
.ekahsdnah a rof dnah sih dednetxe eh erofeb dias semaJ
.dedulcnoc tnemtnioppa eht sa eciffo eht fo tuo detrocse erew owt eht
,thgiew tnerruc s’noxiD koot smailliW .rD
.dnim s’semaJ ni deregnil noillats redlo gnipparts eht
”retnuocnE railimaF“   :yojne esaelP
noillats nagroM tuntsehc rednels dna derutats llew a saw
.terces a sliated lanosrep emos peek ot snosaer rieht dah tneilc yrevE
,yawa setunim wef a ylno saw evird eht elihW
,klat llams fo dexim erew sllah eht sa
,meht neewteb pag eht desolc semaJ
.taog enipla eht fo eciton koot dna
.eciffo s’rotcod eht ta detset tog I yhw si hcihW
.htimS noxiD si eman ehT“
enam etihw gniwolf gnol a dah eH
.snoitatcepxe semaJ teem t’ndid esuohhtab eht fo rocéd ehT
”!dah I keew eht eveileb t’ndluow uoY
emit tsal eno ygolonimret lacidem elbissop lla fo tsil kcehc eht nwod nar yllatnem semaJ
.depleh eb t’ndluoc ti ,revewoh ,esac siht nI
,gnihtolc sih fo erom deppirts eh sa hguohT
.selur eht lla deyalpsid taht ngis eht ta detniop eh elihw
!uoy ot taht od dna yrt dluow enoemos eveileb t’nac I“
noillats retrauq naciremA ruf nedlog ralucsum tes yvaeh a saw thgir eht nO
detavele ti peek noxiD taht dednemmocer llits smailliW .rD
.ereh eb t’nac I ,netsiL“
.partskcoj etihw a htiw nroda
,ydob sih ot gnittif mrof saw trihsrednu etihw dna tekcaj naej s’noillats eht ,eritta sih roF
revo dekool snoillats rehto owt ehT
.ybraen myg eht morf er’yehT ?syug esohT“
hctaw sih ot nwod dekool semaJ
.ruoted a gnikat sselnu ssap t’ndluow sretummoc tsom taht
,ngis yvaeh a tuo tel noxiD
”?uoy ekil yug emosdnah a nwod gninrut enoyna enigami t’nac I
,ereh ti ekil t’nod I esuaceb toN
seitilibisnopser boj sih fo sdnuob lamron eht edistuo pets ot dediced eH
.stnemilpmoc dna ,krow ralloc eulb
.dengis eh retfa sdnah sih debbur semaJ ”!krow fo edistuo
.nwod detfird seye sih erofeb deddon semaJ