.noxiD dniheb dekool oznE
.dias ylmrif kcocaep ehT
,setunim wef a retfA
.niaga drawrof denrut eh erofeb
.mih dewodahsrevo tnaruatser eht sa dessorc mra sih htiw doots eH
.gnihtemos uoy ksa ot gninaem neeb ev’I ,wonk uoY“
,nades eht otni kcab debmilc enoyreve ecnO
,elcitra eht ot dehcatta saw hpargotohp A
semaJ ot revo decnalg dna sunem rieht edisa tes adniL dna noxiD
”.srehto eht dna adniL htiw hcuot ni tpek llits I
,em tsurT“ ,dekrims semaJ
,flesmih demoorg dna derewohs dah eh retfA
”.egaugnal ngis hguorht
,mih rof tnaem ylurt erew stfig eht rehtehw tuoba tnemmoc lufyalp a edam noxiD
.unem eht revo kool a ekat syug uoy tel ll’I ,yawynA“
.tseb ruoy did uoY
.reilrae degguh owt uoy nehw no gniog erom gnihtemos saw ereht thguoht I ,tsrif tA“
.seye s’taog enipla eht ni pu dellew sraet
”!ni delttes syug uoy teg em tel ,emoC
.potretnuoc eht morf dewollib setalp toh gnimaets was yeht sa
.ylediw dennirg oznE dna deddon noxiD
.rehtruf yna eugra ot dessarrabme dna demahsa oot
...I ...adniL“ .dednopser adniL
.noitcerid rieht gnicaf tas tneserp erew ohw stseug eht fo enoN
,desimorp dah repapswen eht ekiL
.flesmih esopmoc ot sdnah sih koohs semaJ
.tfel eh erofeb ssik a semaJ evig ot nwod denael dna deddon noxiD
.moor eht ni esle enoyreve htiw tcatnoc eye gnikam dediova dna
.ereht saw tnemitnes eht tub
.rac s’semaJ eveirter ot telav eht rof detiaw oirt eht sa
edis ot edis morf daeh sih denrut noxiD
.reterpretni na sa ti tuc evah t’ndluow I neht ti eldnah t’ndluoc I fi
.seivom doog leef yb deripsni teg taht epyt eht er’yeht fi esrow yllaicepse s’tI“ .derekcins noxiD
ecalkcen dlog niht a htiw flesreh denroda dah ssenoil ehT
,enog ssenoil eht htiW
”.noxiD ,seot sih no mih gnipeek era uoy dalG
.ytinummoc faed eht ni tsaf daerps ot sdnet drow tub ,yadot noitubirter ees ton yam yehT
don deticxe na evag eerht llA .deksa oznE
.eciov sih desiar kcocaep ehT
.elpoep rehto ot tuo emoc ot tluciffid neeb tsuj s’ti ,wonk t’nod I“
.gnivil a rof sreterpretni emoceb nac elpoep denrael I woh s’taht dnA
)seirotsd2( ta egap yrrufoS sih dna goDdliWD2@ rettiwt no mih wollof nac uoY.sevitcepsrep
dneirf detsurt a dnuora
,dnim ni ytrap llams a htiW
.sserd liatkcoc a gniraew eb ll’ehs ,puY“
;dael s’noxiD dewollof puorg eht
.tnemngissa na no saw eh revenehw ybsressap morf serats emas esoht eviecer semitemos dluow eH
,tsoc tnatibroxe eht rettam oN
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.elacspu erom erehwemos dnetta ot ekil ylbaborp dluow ehs dnA
.noitnetta rieht teg ot meht fo htob eht ot devaw adniL sa
.etad a no erew ohw srevol naht rehtar sdneirf lauxesoreteh fo elor eht emussa ot dah htob yeht hguohT
.guh eht morf flesmih desaeler yltneg taog enipla eht
.evol uoy denethgirf evah ot yrros
.dniw dloc eht morf meht dedleihs ydob ralucsum s’noillats eht
detniop kcocaep ehT ”!tuo teg
,eye s’semaJ fo renroc eht fo tuO
,dengis eh erofeb
der esor peed a dehsulb ecaf s’noxiD ”!yadhtrib yppaH“
saw semaJ ”.elbat tnereffid a su dnuof ro retteb ti denialpxe evah dluoc I fI
tnemom a rof noitseuq eht tuoba thguoht semaJ
.srotaderp tneulffa eb ot dednet srotisiv lamron eht taht testuo eht morf raelc saw ti
noitacol taerg a tnaruatser eht demeed eletneilc eht demees ti
”!dnatsrednu ot deen elpoep gniraeh ecnereffid yek eht s’tahT
sevlesmeht tsgnoma gningis erew adniL dna noxiD
rof rehto hcae nwonk ev’ew dnA
”!ekauqhtrae rojam rehtona gnivah erew ew thguoht I
.sehsid rieht derovas oirt eht sa
raey tsrif sti ni delggurts dah tnaruatser sih woh denialpxe eH
,deipucco ylesraps saw renid eht edisnI
semaJ ot dengis ssenoil ehT
scipot detfihs adniL dna noxiD
.sevitcepsrep wen ot pu sredaer nepo ot yaw a sa gnitirw sesu ohw
?mih emalb uoy naC“ .delggig adniL
.dnetta ot noitavreser rennid a dah llits yeht
?snosaer gnorw ehT“
seugaelloc werc noitcurtsnoc sih fo noitrop egral a taht htuom fo drow s’noxiD ot sknaht neeb dah tI
.elbmert esnetni eht morf denepo seye s’taog enipla nworb dna kcalb ehT
egareveb sih knird ot revo dehcaer noxiD
.ecneirepxe gninid lausac a eb ot deredisnoc yeht tahw rof
.sreterpretni sih no drah neeb syawla s’eh
.egaugnal ngis tuoba erom gninrael ni tseretni ym dekraps dah evetS htiw pihsdneirf ym ,llitS
.retirwepytelet tra-eht-fo-etats sih ta yawa depyt eh sa
revo deklaw dah noxiD
.dniheb dewollof semaJ elihw rood eht derewsna eh
.reilrae gniyrc rof yrros ,haeY“
.elpoep faed htiw egaugnal ngis esu ot sesufer esle enoyreve esuaceb eno deen I
?neht su fo eerht eht eb tsuj lliw ti ,oS !wonk ot dooG“
,noitaudarg retfa dnA
.txen tae ot erehw esoohc ot noxiD wolla ot deerga enoyrevE
"?epoh I dooG ?ti saw woh ,oS"
,serutseg enecsbo ekam ot ereh ton era eW
”?teem uoy fo owt eht did woH
.seye sih debbur dna nway yvaeh a tuo tel
elims mraw a mih dehsalf noxiD
.ciffart gnineve eht otni degrem ylkciuq eh
.od dluow noxiD gnihtemos ekil sdnuos yletinifeD“
”?taht ksa uoy dluow yhW“
.siht ekil nwod nekorb dah eh ecnis sraey neeb dah tI
.hguone riaf ,thgirlA“ ,deddon adniL
”?uoy fo trap taht tpecca t’ndluow I kniht uoY
?su fo eerht eht neewteb tsuj siht peek uoy dluoc
noitacol eno ot nwod ti deworran eh
.scitna lufyalp s’noxiD ta deyonna ylurt t’nsaw eH
.stseretni sih debbarg yletaidemmi taht
,snoitautis lufsserts ylhgih htiw gnilaed ni gniniart lanoisseforp sih fo esuaceB
dluow ,tluda faed a fo dlihc a eb ot neppah t’ndluow uoy
.atsap pmirhs nujaC detseuqer adniL elihw regrub ralimis a deredro dah noxiD
,deunitnoc adniL dna deddon semaJ
.daor eht no kcab seye sih denrut eh erofeb
”.esac eht t’nsi taht dalg m’I tuB
tnaruatser ycnaf a ot enoyreve taert ot gniog saw eH
.efil raed rof no dleh dna
sdnoces wef a rof renwo kcocaep eht ta deralg noillats ehT
.unem eht ffo gnihtyreve deredro eh ,ni emac nam siht yad tsrif eht ,uoy llet I“
.gnikrap rof enil ni dellup semaJ sa
”,thginot ,gnihtyreve rof yrros os m’I“
,demialcorp dna oznE ot denrut noxiD
”?adniL dna ,flesym ,uoY
.meht ekil elpoep htiw gnilaed ni tniop on s’ereht
.noxiD tem tsrif eh woh tuoba
,woN !seitirohtua eht nommus lliw I neht ,setunim owt ni evael ot esufer uoy fI
”.meht kcuf yas I neht ,yenom ruo tnaw t’nseod tnaruatser taht fI
.noxiD detisiv tsal ehs ecnis deneppah dah tahw fo yrammus feirb a evag adniL
detaes ylkciuq erew eerht ehT
”.os ro raey a tuoba
.nwod gnilttes erofeb ereh ycnega na dnuof dna
.myg emas eht ni dednetta dah owt eht dna
eritta lamrof imes sih no dils eh emit eht yb noonretfadim saw ti
.secnalg suoiruc evag snortap rotaderp eht fo wef a eciton tub pleh t’ndluoc semaJ
”.hguoht gninraw eht etaicerppa I
”.gnivrats saw I tfihs ym fo dne eht yb dna hcnul ym hguorht denrub I
.stneidergni hserf htiw edam saw laem eht dna lufitnelp erew snoitrop ehT
.repapswen eht ot kcab noitnetta sih denruter neht semaJ
.nekahs t’ndah sllaw ybraen dna roolf eht taht dezilaer eh
.riahc tevlev der eht otni delttes adniL sa
pit yramotsuc a meht tfel eH
.dehguoc ylivaeh eh sa slirtson s’noxiD morf tuo demaerts retaW .deksa adniL
.ta derats enoyreve taht ytrap rehtona t’nsaw ereht erus ekam ot dnuora dekool eH
!emit doog a evah ot su detnaw tsuj I“ .dias noxiD
.redluohs sih deppat ylthgil dna
.nehctik eht ot txen saw taht rood llams a morf deraeppa kcocaep elam egral a
.gnidnatsrednusim a neeb evah tsum ereht tub ezigolopa I“ ,ekops semaJ
,dengis dna sdnah yklub sih pu thguorb onihr ehT
.thgin eht fo tser eht rof noisnet eht desae dah
,terces a pihsnoitaler rieht fo tnetxe eht peek llits ot deerga owt eht elihW
.noxiD ot seirettalf mraw reh evag ehs sa dnah eno htiw ngis llits dluoc ssenoil faed eht hguohT
.sdneirf gniraeh s’noxiD fo eno eb tsum uoY
”,evael ot puorg ruoy ksa ot em ecrof lliw uoy neht esnesnon siht htiw esaec t’nseod elbat ruoy fI
.serutseg enecsbo yna esu ton ot ereh enoyreve ksa ot deen I tub ,gnitpurretni rof em nodraP“
.noitcetorp rof htaenrednu delwarc dna
,kcans tnasaelp a rof edam daerb elbat hserf eht elihW
.noillats eht ot revo dekool adniL
.eurt yllacinhcet saw dias semaJ tahw sa
,esirprus s’semaJ dna noxiD oT
”.ytsur gnitteg morf em peek ot noxiD ekil enoemos evah I taht pleh seod ti hguohT
etsat rieht rof noitpo tseb eht eb dluow tahw dessucsid dna
,tnelis emaceb moor ehT
.emoh eurt ym deredisnoc I erehw si loohcs tnomerF ehT
,eerht pot eht ot nwod ti deworran eh erofeB
pit rehtona telav eht evag llits eh
.yrots siht rof tnatlusnoc evitaerc faed a sa detca ohw
.niaga uoy ees ot doog ,yob ym ,noxiD“ .skeehc s’noxiD fo htob dessik dna
.nwod flesmih demlac eh setunim wef a retfa dna deddon semaJ
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
?wonk uoy ,siht ekil gnihtemos htiw htrof emoc ot drah s’ti
guh a rof degnul oznE
”,gnihtemos ro deppacidnah yllacisyhp saw I ekil dnuora em tsissa yllacisyhp ot deirt reterpretni knim a ,sweivretni boj wef tsrif ym gnirud derebmemer I ,haey hO“
,meht dniheb tuhs demmals saw rood tnorf eht ecnO
.kcab dengis noxiD
tnaruatser eht detneuqerf dah
,tnemhsilbatse eht ta ezag delzzup s’semaJ dna adniL deciton noxiD
”.uoy htiw drawrofthgiarts yrev s’ehs fi yllanosrep ti ekat t’nod tsuj ...ereh
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,semaJ ot revo dekool neht ehS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ciffart og dna pots ni ruoh na flah tsomla ekat llits dluow ti
.yawateg hcaeb dna ,noisses gnilwob
.meht dehcaorppa ylsuorogiv dna
”?gnitad neeb owt uoy evah gnol woh ,oS“
.ytinutroppo yreve ta elbat rieht dediova yltneuqerf reilrae morf retiaw reed ehT
.thginot bat eht revoc uoy erus ekam ot gniog osla m’I“
.saw melborp eht tahw tuo erugif dluoc eh os tiaw ot meht fo owt eht dlot semaJ
lamron ot denruter gnihtaerb siH
."éfaC eniviD" eht dellac
.tnomerF ni loohcs laitnediser emas eht dednetta htob eW“ .deksa semaJ
.0991 raey eht rof sedalocca ynam htiw tnemhsilbatse eht denroda dah repapswen ehT
.noitanitsed rieht ta devirra oirt eht
,sivaD suiraD yb ”tsaeF citsatnaF“
.noitasrevnoc eht rof yrassecen saw tahw delaever ylno eh ,dnim sih nI
.selbat eht dettod selpuoc seiceps retni fo xim a
,elims yls a htiw sgnaf reh dehsalf dna
”?yenom eht rof tsuj ti gniod ekiL
”!thginot su fo lla rof gniyap llits er’uoy dnA
”!sesimerp eht etacav ot ytrap ruoy gniksa won ma I ,tseuqer ym htiw gniylpmoc ton era uoy ecniS“
puorg s’noxiD ot revo doof rieht deirrac oznE
.sdneirf faed fo elcric renni s’noxiD htiw detniauqca llew gnitteg ot drawrof dekool semaJ
,noitces yraniluc eht deweiver eh emit eht yB
.deripsnart tahw dootsrednu ylticilpmi yeht
,ydaer dna desserd ylluf noxiD htiW
demees tnaruatser eht
ecaf sih no ylduorp deretsalp saw elims yhtoot s’oznE
,stekcaj tius deriuqer taht stnemhsilbatse rehto ot derapmoc suoiruxul-artlu t’nsaw éfac siht elihW
,sunem meht dedivorp oznE sa nevE
semaJ ta erats denrecnoc a dehsalf noxiD
.sngis cisab esu dna llepsregnif ot woh em thguat ylno adirolF ni dednetta I sessalc dna bulc eht
...ereh deiduts I litnu egaugnal ngis laer nrael t’ndid ylpmis I“ ,dednopser semaJ
keehc s’semaJ ot hcuot eltneg rehtona evag noillats ehT
.ekawa derettuhs semaJ sa emarf sserttam eht koohs elttar suorednuht A  sivaD suiraD yb
.flesmih gniyojne morf mih reted t’ndluow serats drawkwa eht
.ecalp s’noxiD ta tneps thgin tsrif sih saw siht ,revewoh
,deunitnoc adniL sa dehgual noxiD
.tnemeticxe eht fo tuo ylniam tub
.meht revo wodahs a detsac dna
,tnemom a rof detegdif noxiD
.niaga noitacifiralc rof deksa dna
.gnikahs pots ot sserttam eht desuac hcihw
”!tsaeb a saw eH
.seitrap rehto morf stnialpmoc lareves deviecer sah elbat ruoy ,ti llac yam uoy revetahW“
.adniL si ereh ssenoil ylevol siht dna semaJ m’I“
.ekauqhtrae egral rehtona rof eud saw aera ehT
,deterpretni semaJ sA
.lavirra s’adniL erofeb eritta lamrof-imes sih otni tog noxiD erus edam eh
shtaerb peed wef a koot taog enipla ehT
”.kram eht no thgir saw I yas I ,snoitcaer ruoy fo htob yb gnigduj tuB
.rebmemer ot enoyreve rof ecneirepxe na htiw noxiD hsival ot regae saw eh
.htuos eht ni devil uoy aedi on dah I
”!enecs a ekam ot ereh ton era eW
,elbat potretnuoc eht ot ytrap eht ediug dluoc retiaw flow eht erofeB
,revewoh ,tuo tfel dah semaJ tahW
,stseug artxe eht htiw neve dnA
.sesruoc egaugnal ngis rieht htiw yppols eb ot dnet segelloc level yrtne fo tol a ,serugiF“
.dnaherofeb yrots kcab elbaveileb a etaerc t’ndid yeht
ot pu erew sdneirf faed rehto s’noxiD tahw no etadpu na evag osla ehS
”.tuo dekcik su gnitteg rof elbisnopser eno eht ton er’uoY
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa reeuq kcalb a
.hsur rennid eht rof eraperp ot selbat ytpme rehto eht dessub dna puorg eht tfel oznE .dednopser noxiD
tub wollof ot snoitcerid taog enipla eht evag eH
”,elbatrofmocnu yrev stseug ruo gnikam er’uoY
”!fo erac nekat si noxiD erus ekam ll’I ,yrrow t’nod tuB
elytsefil rolehcab eht gnivil pots ot noillats eht rof deen eht dezisahpme ehS
.edisbus t’ndid snortap rotaderp rehto eht morf serats eht dnA
,yawa selim wef a ylno saw noitanitsed eht hguohT
.yad taht tfihs ruoh evif-ytriht a dekrow dah I“
.edistuo yaw rieht edam puorg eht sa nwod daeh sih tpek semaJ
deb eht fo egdel tseraen eht otno debbarg eH
”.JJ em sllac noxiD
.seiromem s’taog eht ni
rengis ecivon yrev a saw oznE taht llet dluoc semaJ
.eil a eb ot yrots sih redisnoc t’ndid eH
.evord eh sa snoitasrevnoc rieht rorrim weivraer eht morf was semaJ
.mra tfel reh htaenrednu dekcut tfig dezis muidem a htiw ni emac adniL
”.enim fo dneirf ssenoil a s’ehs dna
.krow fo edistuo rehto hcae otni gnipmub tpek ew dna enim fo tneilc remrof a saw noxiD“
.21 hguorht K stneduts faed stroppus dna sesuoh taht loohcs a s’tI
,thgin eivom lanoisacco eht neeb dah erehT
”!tsaef citsatnaf a ylurt saw tI“
,deunitnoc eh erofeb ,redluohs s’noxiD deppat oznE
.emag strops eht hctaw ot enoyreve rof potretnuoc rennid eht fo renroc eht evoba gnuh
,dehgual ylbidua noxiD
hsilyts saw taht trihs sserd hguone egral a dnuof semaJ
ot sknaht laiceps a ,oslA
meht derussaer ylkciuq eh tub
mih ot repsihw ot ni denael retiaw reed ehT
”tsaeF citsatnaF“ saw sihT
.yad yreve pu ekaw ot ti esu I ,haeY“ ”?mralA“
.renwo kcocaep duorp eht desacwohs ti
.repap eht denepo neve eh erofeb dnim sih deugalp taht seciohc fo arohtelp a ydaerla erew erehT
.onihr eht ot devaw adniL sa denialpxe semaJ
.sserd liatkcoc elprup dilos lufetsat a ni devirra ehs ,reilrae denoitnem noxiD sa tsuJ
,kcab dengis noxiD .dias oznE
.evael ot dedeen yeht meht dlot dna
eadnus ananab eht tuo thguorb neht oznE
puorg eht denioj eh erofeb
nikpan htolc a otno daerb sih fo tser eht pu taps ,dnah rehto eht no ,noxiD
.roolf eht no deltrats ylbisiv dekool noinapmoc taog enipla sih woh was eh
.seiceps lla rof sepicer dna slaem dah renid naciremA siht taht
.sevitaler ro stnerap faed yna evah t’nod I ,oN“ ,dekrims semaJ
.desirprus m’I yas t’naC“ ,dehgual adniL
,sevitaler faed yna evah t’nod uoy ecnis dnA
deb eht fo tuo debmilc eH
smailliW adniL si eman reH
.elbat eht no ti werht eh erofeb
semaJ ot revo dekool adniL ”!yaw eht yb dnA
.ecim telav desserd-llew wef a ot droccA adnoH elpmis sih derednerrus eh
stseug rennid eerht lla evoba deralf srehtaef egral sih
.raey tsap eht rof gnitad ylevisulcxe neeb dah yeht ,neht ecniS
”!tnaig a s’eH !tuo denrut eh woh kool dna yob gniworg a saw eH
.gnihtaerb sih lortnoc ot deirt dna
rehto hcae ot derutseg yltsom eW ?xis ro evif
,deb s’nam rehtona ni dekan eid ot tuoba t’nsaw eh ,sseldrageR
.dleif eht ni krow sih morf lavorppasid lareneg dna ,seralg elitsoh ,stnemmoc dniknu gnitteg ot desu saw eH
.meht ediseb taes reh koot ehs erofeb dniheb morf guh a noxiD evag ehS
.reh teem ot regae m’I !taerG“
.worb sih htaenrednu demrof taews sa dewollaws semaJ
.ylreporp ngis ot flesruoy deniart dna evitaitini eht koot uoy dalg m’I
?oga sraey owt ekauqhtraE ateirP amoL
”tsaeF citsatnaF“   yojne esaelP
.tnaruatser eht fo eman eht yficeps t’ndid
.ecnartne tnorf eht ta
,daor eht no setunim wef a retfA
.mih nekorb dah ti tuoba gnihtyna od ot elbanu dna yadhtrib s’noxiD no tnemhsilbatse na morf tuo dekcik eb ot tuB
;emoh sih ni thgin etad yreve dedne yllausu semaJ
.troppus ym evah syawla lliw uoY
elbat eht no dedivorp daerb eht no dekcans yletaidemmi noxiD
,huH“ ,worbeye na desiar noxiD ".nwod
,adniL decaf dna pu flesmih denaelc ylluf dah noxiD
etomer a debbarg dna deb eht fo edis sih ot revo dehcaer eH
,noitasrevnoc eritne eht no neek t’nerew yeht hguoht nevE
...dnuora saw I nehw evetS deman dneirf retto faed a dah I
”!ereh eb ot yppah tsuJ !uoy knahT“
pu daeh sih detfil ylluferac semaJ
.tfig sih noxiD dednah adniL erofeb hgual llams a derahs eerht ehT .dekniw adniL
,loohcs hgih dehsinif I retfA
.rehtegot emit ytilauq ...emos dneps dluoc owt eht os moordeb retsam eht sdrawot dedaeh yletaidemmi yeht ,esuoh s’noxiD edisni ecno ,rehtaR
”.sselecirp si ecaf ruoy no noisserpxe eht ,hguohT
rennam cilbup a hcus ni dessik eb oT
.elims ekaf a htiw demihc kcocaep ehT
,detcejretni adniL
noillats etihw dna kcalb ralucsum llat ehT
.taes reh ni kcab delttes ehs erofeb lavorppa fo don a evag ssenoil ehT
.lla retfa yadhtrib sih llits saw ti llaretfA
.dellatsni erew taht secived evitsissa eht denoitnem ron
.metsys mrala lacisyhp a ekil gnihtemos evah ot nosrep faed a rof esnes erom edam ti wenk eh ,thgisdnih nI
.detraped retiaw reed eht erofeb sredro knird s'adniL dna noxiD deterpretni semaJ dna
,retiaw tnereffid a htiw sredro rieht decalp oirt eht retfA
.efilthgin gnineve eht fo weiv wodniw ecin a ot ssecca meht dewolla hcihw potretnuoc eht yb tas oirt ehT .ekops oznE
.keehc s’semaJ fo sedis eht nwod dellor yeht ,gnol erofeB
.ecnahc yb myg emas eht dednetta neve eW
elbat nedoow llams a fo tnorf ni tas ydaerla dah noxiD
”?tcerroc ,hsilgnE ni gningis uoy dah yltsom yeht ,sseug em teL
.rof ezigolopa ot gnihton evah uoy
stseug rennid faed ym htiw gnitacinummoc ma I rehtar
regrub nagev eht morf emac taht secips fo amora euqinu yrevE
derebmemer semaJ sa devil trohs saw ysatnaf ehT
noxiD htiw tuo gninid yojne ot dednetni semaJ
.etad a emoh thguorb eh revenehw sessalg eht esu dna
tnemeerga ni sdaeh rieht deddon enoyrevE .dednopser adniL
.sknaht sih dengis yldetaeper dna
,dengis ehs erofeb dnah sih koohs adniL .dengis eH
...tuB .ma I ohw rof em tpecca uoy wonk ot yppah em ekam seod tI
ruoh hcnul sih gnirud ecalp eht detneuqerf dah eH
.moorhtab eht esu ot flesreh desucxe adniL
yldneirf faed erew secalp tahw aedi retteb a dah ylbaborp noillats ehT
.gniltsub dna ralupop ylediw
!ti troppus ylluf I neht ,yppah uoy sekam pihsnoitaler yag a ni gnieb fi dnA
.draug ffo thguac tsom eht saw noxiD
,gnola deddon semaJ
.rocéd lufetsat s’tnaruatser eht no detnemmoc yeht sa
.oznE renwo onihr eht htiw tahc dluow dna
.gnidliub llaw kcirb egral a ot txen dekrap puorg eht
.ereh er’uoy taht si srettam taht llA
?loohcs laitnediser A“
.sehsid reziteppa yrovas emos htiw ffo thgin eht gnitrats ot drawrof dekool semaJ
.puorg s’semaJ ta detniop dna
hguoht nosnhoJ semaJ m’I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.dengis noxiD ”?JJ ,retteb gnileeF“
.adniL dna noxiD rof terpretni ot dah semaJ ,elihw eht llA
”.sdneirf faed ruo fo tser eht htiw nepo eb ot ydaer m’I litnu tsael tA
”,yadot yadhtrib s’noxiD etarbelec nac ew os nwot otni emac eW
.snoicipsus yna esiar t’ndid taht yaw a ni
.slaem rieht meht detneserp dna
.elpoep faed gniees ecneirepxe tsrif snortap eht ylbaborp saw ti derugif semaJ
.thgin eht rof meht etadommocca dluow dna
.esab remotsuc elbats a dedeen dna
.revo emoc ot dennalp dah sdneirf faed sih fo wef a dna yadhtrib htfif ytriht s’noxiD saw yadoT
.tluaf ruoy ton s’tI“ .delffins semaJ
”.gnineve ecin a evah ot su detnaw tsuj I
.yawa dellup noxiD erofeb sdnoces wef a rof deregnil tI
,nwod dekool ylpmis semaJ
.dneirf tsrif ym ylurt saw eH
,rettiwt no lsaflowekaw@
.regnol tib a tsuj smra s’revol sih ni ediser dluoc eh dehsiw semaJ
”.retal hcum llit trap rammarg eht tuoba nrael t’ndid I
noitasrevnoc eht fo sespmilg dna skaep gnikat deyojne ylpmis
ruof tsap ytnewt saw tI
.moorhtab retsam eht otni detaerter noinapmoc taog sih elihw delkcuhc noillats ehT
?yaw eht yb ,sdneirf emoceb owt uoy did woH
puorg sih ot denrut eh sdnoces wef a retfA
.sunem rieht deweiver oirt eht sa
,thginot rof hguohT
,rettam t’ndluow tI“ .noxiD yb deppots
.taht ekil gnihtemos droffa reve dluoc stnerap gniraeh ruo fi sA“
.meht fo owt eht ot pu dekool dna
,noisserpxe tnedifnoc a htiw deilper eH
.tnaruatser laedi tsom eht rof hcraes sih nageb dna
,retiaw reed a yb elbat rieht ot del erew oirt eht sA
.tnemhsilbatse eht fo renroc rehtona ni selbat eht gnissub deunitnoc ,elihwnaem ,oznE dnA
,noitanalpxe eht htiw deifsitaS
”?sdneirf ruoy era ohW
.sretiaw eht rof dnuora dekool semaJ elihw
.dneirf ruoy fo tnorf ni uoy ssarrabme ot naem t’ndiD
;em deloof ev’dluoc uoY
”,xat gniraeh a ti redisnoc ,lleW“
.doohdlihc ecnis rehto hcae nwonk ev’ew ,noxiD“
”?uoy lliw ,nwod taht evil em tel ot gniog reven er’uoY“
.tressed eht ni delapmi snoops ynihs eerht htiw
laem dekooc emoh a htiw
semaJ .tnomerF ni kcab
.taht egnahc reve lliw gnihton dna dneirf tseb ym er’uoY
.renwo na fo daehkcid kcocaep taht saw dessarrabme eb dluohs ohw eno ylno ehT
krow s'taog enipla eht fo edistuo
.dnim ym deppils evah tsum ti sseuG
.taht tuoba nettogrof t’nevah llits uoy ees I“ ,dekrims semaJ
.deripsnart tahw rof elbisnopser neeb t’ndah yeht sa
.em ssarrabme t’ndid uoY“
reh ot revo deklaw semaJ
,yletinifed hO“ ,dennirg adniL
,thgin eht dneps ot esle ecalpemos dnif nac eW
,worbeye desiar a htiw semaJ ot revo dekool noxiD
?laem a retfa teg syawla uoy eadnus ananab taht ,noxiD dnA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ytirahc fo esnes a fo tuo noisseforp eht denioj ohw sreterpretni wen fo tol a tem ev’I tub ,yltcaxe toN“ .deksa semaJ
dnah tfel sih htiw pu nihc s’semaJ detfil yltneg noxiD
.ydaerla sredro rieht ekat ot retiaw nmad a teg tsuj dluoc eh ylno fI
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.slamina rotaderp rehto morf sreel deifisnetni eht deppots t’ndah taht tuB
.spil s’revol sih no ssik wols mrif a detnalp dna
eritta lamrof-imes erow eletneilc eht fo tsoM
.sgnidnuorrus sih dekcehc dna
!em fo tuo sthgilyad eht deracs ti llew ...hO“
,evitcepsrep s’semaJ morF
!ti eta uoy dna enoyreve rof ilihc taht gnikam yad lla tneps I
rehto hcae otni depmub deedni dah yehT
,pu doots dna dnuora denrut semaJ
.slirtson sih deraelc dna
.dlihc ylno na sa eldnahnap adirolF eht ni nwot llams a ni pu werg I ,lleW“
.JJ ,sesirprus fo lluf llits er’uoy
.dnah ni sknird tnagele dna
.sloohcs laitnediser esoht fo eno ot tnew ylbaborp dna retal raey a yawa devom eh ,yldaS
?htiw nigeb ot egaugnal ngis nrael ot uoy deripsni tahW
.snosaer gnorw eht rof noisseforp eht denioj uoy taht deirrow tib a saw I ,hguohT
”?noisseforp gniterpretni eht ni detseretni uoy edam tahw
.nwod desolc gnieb morf ti devas nrut ni dna
.taes sih ni dnuora mriuqs mih edam noitarbelec yadhtrib dna etad rennid eht tuoba tnemeticxE
noitacol eht no delttes semaJ
,deunitnoc adniL .dettimda noxiD
,elims thgirb a mih dehsalf dna
.yllautneve pu emoc dluow s’adniL ekil noitseuq a derugif ydaerla dah semaJ ,revewoH
VT deroloc yklub A
”.emit rehtona meht htiw laed lliw I dna noxiD ,su tsurT
.guh a rof ni mih dellup noillats eht erofeb ediskcab dna sredluohs sih ekorts yltneg
.mih wonk ot teg dna noxiD htiw niart dluow I derugif I ,oS
.sdneirf esolc s’noxiD fo eno teem yllanif ot ecin s’tI“
semaJ degdun yltfos noxiD
.spil enilef reh deffup adniL
.tnemeticxe htiw pu dezies hcamots s’semaJ edam
.keehc s’taog enipla eht dezarg dna
snoitacol wef a elcric ot nugeb ydaerla dah eh
.noitnetta s’dneirfyob sih teg ot elbat eht rednu morf s’semaJ tsniaga gel tfel sih debbur noillats eht
.yadhtrib sih tuoba noitseuq a mih deksa oznE taht wenk dna sdrow eht fo emos tuo ekam dluoc noillats ehT
.yad eht rof ydaer gnitteg saw tnatropmi erom saw tahw ,won thgiR
.seralg detaicerppanu mih evag meht fo ytirojam eht ,tcaf nI
emoh sih fo ruot a mih nevig t’ndah noillats ymaerd ehT
.ydob sih otni deddebme noitailimuh dna emahs rettu eht sa revo dehcnuh saw erutsop siH
etsat eht yb deifsitas
.yb gnuws taht dik egelloc a morf taht denrael I“
.tixe eht drawot yaw rieht edam yeht sa
deddon kcocaep ehT
nehctik eht sdrawot denrut ylneddus noitnetta s’puorg ehT
.pu dekrep dnarts ruf laudividni hcae edam
”?noxiD thgir ,sepyt eht wonk uoY
”.eno nrehtuos a naht erom tcelaid tsaoc tsew a stcelfer elyts gningis ruoy
,epoN" .deksa noxiD
,retal snikpan ynam htiw deilppuser erew yeht retfA
.ti ekam t’ndluoc tser eht sa gnineve siht revo gnimoc si nosrep eno ylno tuo snruT“ ,dengis noxiD
,dedlofnu dah gnineve eht woh etipseD
”?loohcs gnidraob etavirp fo dnik emos taht sI
”?taht saw htrae no tahW“
drawrof denael eH
?dnatsrednu ,thgir noillats ym taert retteb uoY“
,desserd ylluf tsomla noillats eht htiW
”,adniL tuoba tol a em dlot reven uoY
.ekat ro evig kcolc’o ruof dnuora ereh ffo reh pord lliw dnabsuh reH
.meht ot dias saw tahw tuoba yrammus feirb a meht evag dna
.edisni adniL dna noxiD dediug dna
.eta yeht elihw renid cificeps siht ot meht thguorb dah noxiD yhw dootsrednu ylkciuq semaJ
.ylteiuq debbos eh sa nar eson siH
”.mrala lamron a htiw raeh nac I ekil ton s’tI
.rehtegot esolc denael meht fo owt eht was dna
”!elbareffusni tsom eht eb ot dnet yehT
.esuohhtab yag a ta rehto hcae ssorca emac yllaitini dah owt eht woh saw
”?mrala eht naem uoY ?tahW“
mra sih htiw skeehc sih fo sedis eht depiw eH
.mih rof tcaf ni erew yeht taht derussa adniL
.smret ruoy no ylno ,esruoc fO“
.secaf s’noxiD dna adniL no detniap snoisserpxe denrecnoc eht was eH
”!ylurt sruoy morf tfig a ti redisnoC !em no s’tahT
ecaf sih epiw ot nikpan ybraen a debbarg noillats ehT
.noitavreser a hsilbatse ot dellac ylkciuq dna
.dedepminu rehtegot tahc dluoc yeht taht os staes raer eht ni tis ot owt eht dewolla eH
”,em fo kniht dluow uoy tahw ...fo diarfa saw I
eht ekil elacs eht no ti saW
,dehsinif yeht retfA
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.selpuoc ni pu deriap eb ot dednet dna
.em ot retsis redlo na ekil s’ehS
,uoy evah I sa gnol oS
,pu dehcnelc traeh s’semaJ
!ti fo enon evah lliw I ,hguonE“
,thgis eht yb desaelpsid saw kcocaep ehT
.redluohs sih deppat noxiD ”.yako eb ll’ew
detnirpmi eb reverof dluow taht eno
.segareveb cilohocla suoirav rof sessalg rab detacitsihpos fo
,thgin eht fo tser eht rof slaem rieht ni degludni ylteiuq eerht ehT
!oot uoy teem ot ecin s’ti dna smailliW adniL m’I“
.noxiD ot dekool oznE "?yadhtrib ruoy s’yadot ,’niloof oN"
.nades revlis sih otni bmilc dluoc yeht taht os
.sessalc egelloc wef a koot dna bulc egaugnal ngis a denioj I
!thgis fo tuo elbat rehtona ot evom nac ew ,uoy fo geb I“
,noitseuq eht yb dennuts sa tsuj saw semaJ elihW
,ruf nworb dna kcalb sih rednu hsulb semaJ edam tnemmoc ehT
.ydob yklub s'noxiD rof gnittif mrof ton tub
,revo dedlof srae s’semaJ
.ereh steg ehs nehW
88 ni deifitrec tog I ,eerged setaicossA ym gnitteg retfa dnA .58 ni ereh loohcs a ot refsnart ot em rof secruoser edivorp pleh bulc eht dah I ,oS
.stcejbus evitisnes etagivan ylluferac ot yrassecen slliks eht denoh dah eh
”.reterpretni na eb tsuj ot delliks oot yaw er’uoY ?uoy
”.erofeb sepyt esoht nees ev’I ,haeY“
”.sdneirf tsaf emaceb llits ew tub ,em evoba edarg eht ni saw adniL
.meht erofeb detneserp eadnus eht htiw
.hsilgnE nrael ot esufer dna sselpleh m’I esuaceb reterpretni na deen I taht hcum os ton s’ti ...ekil s’tI“
raef fo tuo yltrap
”?wonk uoy paehc emoc t’nseod gniniarT“
.dias nameltneg kcocaep eht tahw yfiralc ot
.eno siht ekil stnemhsilbatse htiw gnilaed ni syaw ruo evah eW“ ,ni demihc adniL
”.gnineve dab a evah reven ll’I
”.nehctik s’loohcs eht ni peelsa tsaf mih dnuoF
kcab dengis semaJ
taes reh ot denruter adniL
,wA“ ,derekcins noxiD
,dnuorg eht no ecnO
.enohpelet yb noitavreser a pu tes dna
,meht morf teef wef a doots ylno llits adniL taht dezilaer eh nehw hguohT
,deruces saw tols gnineve eht ecnO
.sdneirf faed rehto sih fo lla dna adniL rof ro
.mih ot dengis semaJ
hgih dleh daeh reh tpek adniL
.esuoh eht edisni derekcilf sthgil llebrood eht nehw
.seirettalf mraw sih evag dna
sdnah mraw egral s’noxiD tlef eH
tnegnat a no tnew onihr eht
,noxiD htiw etad citnamor a no tuo og ot ytinutroppo ylno
.stcejorp gnitirw erutuf rof
.sgnirrae duts dlareme reh detnemilpmoc taht
,thgir s’ehS“ .dengis adniL
.sehtolc sih deveirter eh elihw ecaf s’dneirfyob sih ta wollip a delruh semaJ
”.dedaol eb tsum uoy ,ruoh rep egrahc sreterpretni uoy setar suolucidir eht roF
edistuo adniL dna noxiD derehsu semaJ
.noitacav no tuo ylimaf reh ekat ot ssenoil eht dewolla kcab shtnom wef a noitomorp reH
telav eht yb egarag gnikrap eht otni derehsu erew srac suoiruxuL
rehtegot meht fo owt eht fo seisatnaf tuo yalp ot nageb dnim sih
suiraD fo dneirf a
.kcultop s’loohcs eritne eht eta eh ,loohcs elddim ni emit enO
toof devooh sih htiw
,nrut sih saw ti nehW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,nepo saw rood eht ecnO
.tsael ta yadot ton
,eraps ot setunim wef a tsuj htiW
sevlesmeht ot eurt eb dluoc yeht gniwonK
noitceles egral a noillats eht thguorb dah ehs
.moor gnivil eht ot tuo dedaeh dna
dezilaer noillats eht sa
.rafa morf enecs eht deweiv enoyreve
;noxiD otno dleh ylthgit eH
.dnaherofeb setad no tuo enog t’ndah noxiD dna semaJ hguoht sa t’nsaw tI
sih eb ylbaborp dluow tI
.snoitrop suoreneg dna
edistuo morf repapswen lacol eht debbarg ,elihwnaem ,semaJ
"!evil I sa gnol sa rof ti tuoba swonk enoyreve erus ekam lliw I
.cilbup rediw eht morf noicipsus tuohtiw
,sivaD suiraD yb
,ksa ot evah I hguohT
.revo dehsur dna nehctik eht morf noxiD dettops onihr tes-yvaeh egral a
.ekawa derrits ylwols noxiD dneirfyob sih woh was dna
.sngis cisab emos esu did ew taht derebmemer I tub