.egamad fo tnetxe eht kcehc ot rorrim a tuohtiw ,ecalp sih ekat ot reed a rof yawa derehsu saw eh esuaceb
sub deretrahc eht draoba ,woN
,reh was eh emit tsal eht eb llew yrev yam ti ,lla retfA
seivvic ni nem gnikrims-won eht ot sdaeh sih dekrej tac eht ,ereH ”—taht erofeb tuB
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ekil ni enam sih devahs t’ndah eH
.flaheb sti no thguof dah taht snoil eht ronoh ot dengised
.rrup s’rehtom sih ta denrut noil ehT ”?ajaR“
.thgirtuo lrans ot ton od dluoc eh lla saw ti dna
,ecapsdaeh worran-oot a yb detabrecaxe saw sihT
.rehtona yb defoor snorvehc kcalb eerht dewohs etteluape tsehc sih
.lanoitome lla tog eh tsel
,sknar sti deretne ohw sretsgnuoy fo enil gnidne-reven eht fo trap saw ajaR won dnA
.yenruoj eht fo hcum rof teiuq neeb ev’uoY“
.tuo-koob tsrif sih ekam ot detnaw eh fi doog yna mih od ot gniog t’nsaw gniyrrow siht lla
.nirg a ni tuo sgnaf sih
.derettam ti lla rof yawa sretemolik fo sdnasuoht eb dluoc yeht
.nwod sliat dna srae ,ytivitca fo yrrulf a ni drawrof dehsur stiurcer ehT ”!EVOM“
,tenalPruF yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a
,eueuq a otni tog ajaR  .was dna srettuc tlob fo riap a
ffo snos rieht gnivaw
.edisni tae ot gnihton saw erehT
,nahtanagneR ajuP demeetsE eht ,rehtafdnarg s’ajaR
;noitresed tneverp ot
.detsilne ro elamef erew uoy fi enam on dah eno taht gniyas nommoc a saw erehT
,sriahc citsalp der ot txen doots strohs dna strihs-T nailivic ni nem lareveS
,dnalg lasanoremov s'ajaR dehcaer
,tnempiuqe lareneg sih fo tser eht tcelloc ot tnew neht eH
,seetsilne rehto fo sdnasuoht htiw dekcap-maj saw hcihw
,enod s’taht retfA“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.spahrep ,smaerd sih nI
?rof stsev rieht no sehcuop omma eht erew esle tahW
.saw eh ,syaw ynam ni dnA
!kcurt lortnoc-fo-tuo na morf swollef sih evas ot gniyrt rof
.mlac fo esnes ddo na tlef ajaR
.gnidliub yrots-evif eht ot detniop tnaegreS eht ,ereH
.tniop on s’erehT“
.etisbew s’esnefeD fo yrtsiniM eht no senilediug eht dettif ti taht erus saw noil eht dna
,sub eht no taht sa luftneve sa saw yrref eht no pirt ehT
.D PMAC TMB OT EMOCLEW
dah eh eciohc elttil eht nevig
?efil remrof sih fo tfel s’revetahw peek ot elba eb eh lliW
.sub nosirp a edisni neeb evah dluoc eh
,ajaR evitiutni-reve
,kcurt dekarb ylreporpmi na yb revo nur gnieb morf nootalp sih evas ot detpmetta dah
ot dessap ohw lla dednimer yalpsid DEL nA
,tsehc sih ni delbmur lworg A
,no saw eh yrref eht dereets dah flesmih norahC ekil tlef ti
”.aedi on evah uoy ,hO“
,saw ecno taht efil sih yawa ekat yam ymra eht
,netsil dluow ohw enoyna ot ”yrujni raw“
.aidem eht dna sevitaler rieht yb dehsawniarb ylhguoroht ro lufraef rehtie
,ecivres emit-lluf rof gniylppa ni erised sih lleuq t’ndid
,ni elcycib a tif ot hguone egral sesac gnillevart thguorb dah emoS
,dnim s’ajaR hguorht gninnur thguoht yrev eht saw tahT
.pils eht meht gnivig deirt eno on gnirusne
.retaw fo ydob a htiw nwo rieht dednuorrus dna decnef
,yttej eht pu edam taht etercnoc deretlehs fo hcterts gnol eht nwod gnikooL
!reidlos reerac a sa no ngis dna
,sreciffo dna sOCN eht fo selims eht derussa ,yrrow t’noD
.erew syug eseht tahw s’taht oS
.attednev erutuf fo doohilekil eht dna eralg a gninrae
yllaiuqolloc dna ,lanimreT yrreF ymrA eht sa yllamrof
.hsurbhtoot a tif ot ecalp a ylerab htiw
.dehsurb ro demmirt ruf rieht evah ot remoorg a ot tnew eno
,”...fo erac nekat eb dluow gnieb-llew s’tik/buc ruoY“ .egats no sreciffo gnidnammoc eht morf secnarussa yb dedrabmob noos erew yeht erehw
.ssecorp eht ni dehsurc tog reve enoyna fi
,”tesdnim evitisop a htiw yad eht tratS“
.ycrem rof seirc dna rethgual lacainam yb deinapmocca
daeh dna srae sih gnitlit ylerem
”.duorp lla su od ll’uoy erus m’I
neercs tilkcab DEL a no niaga dna emit skaerf daednu pu gniwolb fo taht dna
.pac gniniart dna stemleh rieht no yrt meht dah srotcartnoc nailivic hcihw fo dne eht ta
.tnempiuqe rehto edisgnola
laremehpe dna sseltniop tey
,eceip eno ni ”pmaC yadiloH“
.srettat ni saw enam sih fo deniamer tahw dna ,eros saw placs siH
dekcots ecalp a ni
edirp gnivres-fles htiw delpuoc
”?ffuts rieht tog enoyrevE“
,tnecsa sih fo tsdim eht ni elzzum eht no lesaew a dekcams ajaR
.redderhS repaP sa elor evitartsinimda na mih evig ot tub eciohc on dah
,htaeD fo wodahS eht fo yellav eht ni klaw I hguohT !edirp evaH .flesmih dlot eh !edutitrof evaH
gniht suoregnad A
.erofeb raegdaeh fo mrof yna nrow d’eh taht toN
,sreidlos 06 tif ot hguone egraL
.etaf fo revir eht nwod gniwolf fael a
,netsil ylno dluoc ajaR .deen reve dluoc eh tnemegaruocne sseltniop eht lla mih evig ot gniunitnoc rehtom s’ajaR htiw
spets dezisrednu dna seldnah decalpsim yb pu fleseno llup ot deriuqer saw scitaborca cisab sa llew sa
,srehtorb sih ot deneppah tahw tuo dnuof reven eH
,sgab elffud kcalb fo lluf delip saw dehs eht
rof lley rebrab eht draeh ylerab eH
.epahs fo tuo tneb gnol
,sregalliv derdnuh a ot emoh eb ot desu dnalsi ehT
.ylmirg spil sih desrup ajaR
.ereh kcab uoy dnes lliw egras ruoy ,ot detnaw I fi nevE
?ajaR ot sneppah tahw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
sretaw detsefni-krahs htiw meht gnidnuorrus yb gnipacse stiurcer tneverp ot saw siht
.delknirw worb reh ,deksa ehs
,laem sih wehc ot emit sih koot ajaR
,tsap dehsalf stiurcer fo nootalp A
.pmac TMB eht nihtiw yal taht srorroh lautca eht fo sksam selzzum rieht
,sdneirf redlo ro sevitaler morf ti eb
”?he ,knilb nac ew naht retsaf gniog s’gnihtyreve ekil skooL“
.sllirf eht fo enon saw ereht ,ymra eht ni tuB
.tinU gniviD yvaN suodrazah tey
sffur dna rufdaeh sih
.luawretac dehctip hgih a ni tac eht deraor
,evitcurtsnoc gnihtemos gniod emit erom tneps dah eh dehsiw ajaR ,reiP htaeD sa
.retrohs kool ti ekam ot dib a ni
.noos oot dexaler dah eh wenk eh dna
.senohp rieht htiw gnilddif
.wor htaed no esoht ekil tsuj
.evaw lausac a rehtom sih evag ajaR
,yltrohs deyalp saw mehtna lanoitan ehT
.tnemnrevog lainoloc eht yb ecivres rof detpecca noos erew srehtorb sih dna eh ,”llik ot lliw“ dna
,ecnelis saw mih dnuorA
rof tnaem raegdaeh rof nwod mih tup dah esaB rewopnaM lartneC eht ni toidi emoS
…roirepus on raef llahs I
noitnem ot detcelgen yltneinevnoc eH
.tiftuo wen rieht ot tuo gniruop seetsilne eht htiw nepo dehsarc etagliat eht sa neve
.gnihtyna fo tuo miws nac yeht gnikniht syawla ,srettO
deffuh ”,aM ,edir etunim neetfif a tsuj s’yenruoj ehT“
.dlrow nailivic eht ni deriuqer taht fo essenif eht teem t’ndid ohw sremoorg ecno erew srebrab yratilim taht sromur erew erehT
,regnol hcum rof eb ton dluow sevil rieht taht gniveileb ,srehtO
.erauqs edarap eht ni
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
nwonk kramdnal suomaf eht sdrawot gnilbmur
.esiwrehto yas ot ecim yna t’nerew ereht dna
.tenretnI eht morf denaelg dah eh
.mih nopu dednecsed revahs cirtcele deniats-emirg eht sa
.enola eramthgin siht reffus t’ndid eh taht was ajaR
,eciloP latnemigeR demra eht morf selims decrof eroM
sOCN ytsrihtdoolb eht gnicaf fo tcepsorp eht yb desare tub lla ,edaf dluow
.ymra eht ni krow dnif ot laog s’efil sih ti edam
,”tnemhsinup sa nevig eb ot spu-hsup ylno“ ,”...elbaliava erac lacidem tseb“
kaerts citsidas a ro eye prahs a rehtie tuB
,drawrof saw yaw ylno eht tuB
,sevlesmeht naht erom elttil thguorb
.revopots tfarcretaw naht
ylhsirevef gnirettum
mih detcepxe ayaJ rM tey dnA
.tnayobmalf ylrevo ro tnarticlacer eht yb stseuqer yllausu erew siht hguoht
?ereh gniod I ma lleh elbanigaminu ,ydoolb eht tahW  2 fo
,mih dnimer ot tif was syawla rehtaf sih sa
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.uoy otni stohs fo yellov rieht esaeler ot depperp dauqs gnirif eht htiw
.siht sa hcus syad tnemtsilne gnirud essam ne derih erew yeht
.slliuq daeh denetrohs rieht taes retteb ot
.revo saw keew eht erofeb pu srae sih wercs dluow taht selohrae dengilasim dna
ecamirg ylno dluoc ajaR
,mih llik t’ndid kcab miws eht fI
,yrref eht fo edis etisoppo eht tA
hguohT .yrc ton dluow eH
,floWisakiM yb snoS ot srehtaF“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.llits kcuf eht dloh dna nwod ssa ruoy tiS ?eerf s’ti kniht uoY
.raw fo snopaew htiw
onihr a dna stnahpele owt
,edalb desurevo na fo noitasnes gniraet eht yb deinapmocca
s’ajaR fo dneirf redlo nA
.egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
.gniniart eht fo erutan eht nevig ,nommocnu rehtegotla ton erew syawawotS
.meht fo tol elohw eht eldnah ot omma hguone dah ylbaborp ohw
.ylkrad thguoht ajaR
,riaffa nmelos a saw tI
.noitcif morf hturt etarapes ot drah saw ti tnaem
,tihs nwo ruoy thguorb ohw uoy fo esoht roF“
,gniniarT yratiliM cisaB ni tnits sih gnirud enif deganam rehtaf ruoY
.srallod owt stsoc mirtruf ehT .timmad ,oN“ .delwocs gnorutnib ehT
stsopetag owt tsap deraor kcurt ehT
yrots s’yadoT dna
gniM tnaegreS delley
1 traP ,floWisakiM yb
.ti ekil meht ekam dluoc eno on tub
,sdeed s’rehtaf sih etalume ot msaisuhtne decalpsim a ro ,laez fo tuO
s’dehs eht taht devresbo ajaR
,sediseB“ .ajaR
.emoh morf raf deksihw gnieb ta erusaelpsid sih gnitnev fo raef rof
llac dedaerd eht emac nehT
.emit ht75 eht ekil rof yrots taht draeh dah eH
.rehto eht revo esoohc dluow yeht hcihw noitseuq on saw ereht hguoht
.emitecaep gnirud gnineppah ti etipsed
,ygolohtym tneicna no koob a ni norahC tuoba daer ecno dah ajaR .lleH fo noisiv s’nam gnuoy yreve ot egdirb A
galf etats eht htiw
,srae s’ajaR hcaer ot detrats sdnammoc delrans dna gnilley fo sdnuos ehT
kcurt eht fo elddim eht ni retto dewalc-llams A
,ecnednepedni niag retal dluow tI
.yllufniap seye sih desolc dna
,deyonna kool t’ndid flow ehT
!ffo erac nekat eb lliw gnieb-llew s’nos ruoy
.reve ebirb tsepaehC
;boj eno ylno dah srebraB
,spil sih dekcil ajaR
,tuo denrut dah mirtruf sih elbirroh woh aedi on dah ajaR
,ruf ’srehto ynam dna sih nopu nwod gnizalb nus eht htiw erauqs edarap eht ni gnidnatS
”!demmirt senam dna rufdaeh ruoy teg lliw os enod t’ndah ohw uoy fo esoht—"—
”—sgab ruoy htiw enil ynapmoc eht fo tnorf ni elbmessa ot era uoy
seimra nredom eht
,thgir sih ot gnikooL
.sgnivigsim emas eht derahs
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
sih fo detsaob neht ecnis dah ayaJ rM
”,ramukayaJ ajaR“ ”?sruoy s’tahW
.sredrob suoiracerp sti dnefed retteb ot yltrohs detcane saw elam yreve rof noitpircsnoc yrotadnaM
.etamilc laciport toh a hcus ni yllaicepse
.yrref dekcap ylluf eht no
,edisni eht no efil fo stnuocca raeh dluoc enO
!gnitae eb dluow nos ruoy tahw si sihT
,deklaw ajaR os dna
.tnialpmoc rof esuac ruoy s’tahw ees t’nod I ,ajaR“
.yaw sih no mih gnireehc dna gnilims llits
elbissop edam etaf A
,lluks sih tsniaga enam sih gninettalf deirt ajaR
.ssenevitnetta rieht no kcehc ot deksat neeb dah stnaegreS emos sa
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.dessap yeht sa talf erew srae rieht taht ees ot emit dah tsuj noil eht
.ymrA eht ni emit s’floWisakiM yb deripsni saw yrots sihT
.ecnaigella fo htao eht yb ni nrows seetsilne eht lla htiw
dekramkcop eb dluow roiretni ehT
,ezorf stiurcer eht llA
.doolb t’nsaw ssenikcits der taht fi denmad eb dluow eh dna
”?srallod owt evah uoY
,kcohs eb ylno dluoc tahw ni ediw seye
,floWisakiM yb ”snoS ot srehtaF“
,raegdaeh delebal ”SSELENAM-ENILEF EGRAL“
,taoc yffulf ylsuolucidir sih peek ot deyomaS eht dessessop lleh eht tahw rednow ylno dluoc ajaR
deussi neeb dah eh taht dnuof kay a retfa ylno saw tI
,wenk enoyna sa raf sA
,stiurcer gnitcerid saw ikseR tnaegreS erehw erauqs edarap eht ot parc sih gniggarD
,dehs gniniart ria-nepo egral a edistuo yltpurba deppots kcurt ehT
”snoS ot srehtaF“   :yojne esaelP
,sgnignoleb sih dloh ot gab regnessem tsedom a dah eH
.did sdinac woh sa ylsuoiruc
,dnuoba saremac dna secnef eht lla htiw tahw
.ekops kcurt eht ni eno oN
sih yal emoh llac ot gnirebmemer dna
.spmac gniniart fo noitcelloc a ot detrevnoc saw ti erofeb
,stserof eht ni erifnug fo sdnuos eht raeh ot detcepxe dah ajaR wohemoS
!stif gnihtyreve erusne dna ,wor yb wor tnempiuqe ruoy tcelloc lliw uoY“
.daetsni lrans a gninrae
”.flesti lleH sti ekil tnemtsilne fo kaeps uoY“
,mih ta tniop ot gnorutnib a desuac
gnuoy rieht dna stnerap ehT
,ffo nos sih ees t’ndluoc eh taht
,esnefed s’ymrA eht nI
.emaf ot mialc detuper sih naht rehtar
;dias ecno tnemailraP fo retsiniM a sa tub ,snoil fo enil yratilim a htiw detaicossa eno boj suoromalg a toN
.dlrow rehtona otni swap rieht tes
.niaga dna emit nevorp dah seitivitca hcus sa
,flesti zartaclA morf tnereffid on dnalsi na no tuB
.edalb s'rebrab eht ot gnillaf ruf ywons fo spmulc retfa pmulc
”?tuoba gniyrrow uoy era tahW
egap koobzzuM a gnidulcni
”?rof gnitiaw uoy era tahW“
.llec sih ni ti tuoba gnihgual eb llits dluow revird kcurt ehT
.yttej a edisgnola werd yrref eht
.yltcefrep dettif ti
.mihw a no retrahc a detfard dah enoemos esuaceb lla
.kcurt eht fo bac eht otni yaw rieht gnikam
.ymra eht fo ysetruoc
stsev TP neerG
,dlrow edistuo eht nI .srebraB
regit eht dna eh ekil skooL
spins nit htiw demmirt rebrab eht hcihw
.edir sih fo noitom eht htiw dekcor elzzum sih sa neve
,stpircsnoc fo thgilp eht ot citehtapmys dog a saw ereht fi nevE
.ekil ot demees yratilim eht kcalb noitaluger eht ni neve saw hcihw
.rennot-5 eht gniliassa stnecs delgnim dna taews fo llems eht
enut gnignahc yldipar a ot gnicnad fo yoj eht ,emit nI
.stiurcer derehtag eht erofeb deppets ohw
,etagliat eht desolc tnaegreS-dr3 a dna revird ehT
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT dna snoitacilbuP tenalPruF yb dehsilbup ,ygolohtna STACDLIW :SEICEPS dna raW fo sgoD eht
,regit a htiw noitasrevnoc ekam ot deirt
,elbayojne neeb dah sbulcthgin owt s’noitan dnalsi eht fo eno ta sdneirf sih htiw gnicnad dna
.rehto eno revo desrepsretni
,semit suoutlumut esoht ni erew yeht sa gnieb sgnihT
.emoc sah emit rieht gniwonk
,nootalp seiceps-itlum a evom ot gnitpmetta noil ynwarcs a ,yletanutrofnU
.eripmE eht fo sehcaer ynam eht ot tnes erew yeht
ailanrehparap dekcap-erp fo elbmuj gatgar a
ni deraeppa ylremrof evah ”snoS ot srehtaF“
lanimret yrref eht dehcaer yehT
taes eht tsniaga drah dehsal liat s’ajaR ”.snoitidart
,ecnednopserroc laiciffo fo snaem yb FTMB ot gnitroper fo srednimer tnatsnoc eht etipseD
.thgin dnoces ro thgin tsrif eht no tresed dluow ohw seno eht erew eseht ,yllacirotsiH
.snoitaredisnoc gniniart rof ytefas dna ecaps elpma gnivah fo snosaer detats eht rof
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,enam sih tuohtiW
.dluow gniniart eht
.tsrif deppiuqe eb ot era yeht oS
srebmuN noitacifitnedI lanoitaN dna
,stroper swen laiciffo eht ot gnidroccA
.ekortstaeh yb demusnoc gnieb erofeb ruoh na tsal t’ndluow eH
.rekaepsduol eht revo reciffo na decnuonna
.aruP ot tnes saw tinu sih hcihw retfa
.dias dah ayaJ rM .dlehpu eb tsum noitidart ylimaf ehT
,sregit lareves dedulcni hcihw
,demees dnalsi yratilim eht lufecaep woh gnisirprus saw tI
.esoprup sti fo erutan eht etipsed
,RH ymrA aka ,ymrA 1G fo krelC feihC eht noos dna
,stiurcer eht ta kcab ylevissapmi derats eH
,revewoh ,esucxe taht detcidartnoc esiotrot a fo ecap eht ta delffuhs llits eh taht tcaf ehT
”.flesti ecivres naht erom htrow si ecivreS eht ot ytlayoL“
yb dednemmoc neve saw dna
,esuohkooc eht ta dedivorp saw ecir nekcihc fo hcnul suoutpmus A
TMB ni tnedicni etanutrofnu taht gnirud
ydaerlA .galf ecivres dna tinu eht yb deknalf
,suoigitserp eht ot derrefsnart neeb ecnis dah eh
.ekila egaggab dna stiurcer gnikrej
.sluos rehto ynam mialc ot dnalniam eht ot denruter won neve hcihw
,noitpircsnoc otni decrof eb yam yehT
.llef enam hsiwolley sih fo shtaws nopu shtaws sa rorroh ni no kool ylno dluoc ajaR
,ti tuoba kniht ot tnemom a rof deppots ajaR fi dna noitasrevnoc ro cisum duolrevo fo sdnuos on erew erehT
.tsap gnihsalf gnidliub detadipalid lanoisacco eht htiw
,tops eros ylralucitrap a ssorca regnif a werd noil ehT
.roloc recin a htiw revo ti tniap dluow yeht spahrep rO
.wodniw eht ot kcab denrut eh sa
.tuoba evitisop eb ot elttil saw ereht taht
ocserf a htiw moor sih fo gniliec eht gnitniap etelpmoc ro
,flesmih yb detaes esroh a ees dluoc ajaR
gniylpmi rehtruf
.repmihw lanoisacco eht htiw detautcnup
.mih ediseb enil ni doots ohw flow a deteerg ”!ereht iH“
,doohnam rieht sa edirp hcum sa htiw senam rieht erow snoil elaM .reve
.eb ot tuo ti edam srehto sa elbirroh sa eb t’now gniniart eht ebyaM
,ylimaf sih ot taht saw gniht cinori eht dnA
nosaer ylekil erom eht saw taht ajaR dlot gnihtemos dna
.edirp sih ekat reven lliw yeht
,ytic trop eht ni ylimaf a detrats eH
,msilavivrus citpylacopa-tsop tuoba koob taht gnitirw sa hcus
.dlohpu ot egami na dah eh ,sediseB
stpircsnoc eht ereh dnA
,esac eht revetahW
.riahc sih otni mih devohs dna
.htaeD fo legnA eht fo
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
,erauqs edarap eht sdrawot yltnelis deddolp yeht ,sriahc rieht morf gnisiR
.thgiarts ecaf sih tpek ajaR
,detaerc neeb dah seueuQ
.flesmih ot yltnelis dehgual ajaR ?kcab sraey ytriht saw ti naht retteb hcum erew sgniht woh no detnemmoc ecno rehtaf sih t’ndah ,lla retfA
.gab leffud gnitsrub-tsomla na otni deffuts
”!swor eerht ni elbmessa ,enoyrevE“
,egalfuomac larutan rieht nevig ,ytud evitca rof derreferp gnieb sregiT etipseD
,snoitnetni doog reh etipseD
.dnalniam eht ot kcab yaw eht flah maws tiurcer debrutsid-yllacigolohcysp a nehw
?netsil tub od eno dluoc tahw tub ,talf srae
,sbmil ym dnuora depparw segadnab htiw ,haeY
”,erauqs edarap eht ta elbmessa dna stnerap ruoy ot eybdoog yas esaelp ,stiurcer llA“
,kaeps ot flesmih gnirb etiuq t’ndluoc ajaR ”.hpmuH“
yrtnuoc eht fo tsewhtron sretemolik net tuoba dnalsi na ,gnakiaS ualuP no detacol pmac gniniart a si ,trohs rof FTMB
,kcab raey a tset eht ot tup neeb dah ytiruces s’pmac dnalsi ehT
”!noitcepsni rof tuo denrut gnihtyreve tnaw I
,kwahom a ni nworg slliuq daeh htiw enipucrop a saw mih ot txen thgiR
.eb ot ton saw sehsif eht htiw noitavlas
.reve fi ,elihw a rof emoh ees ton dluow yeht taht gniwonk
.dekcol ylbaborp erew kced eht ot srood eht ,sediseB
.pils eht sOCN rieht evig ot eganam yeht dluohs
,saw eh sa detaesuan sa
,ajaR morf yawa llib citsalp eht deksihw rebrab eht ,ffuh a htiW
.ssargnomel dna nekcihc fo etsat eht ni gnihsiler
pac dna temleh sih gnivig ,”ENIVOB DENROH“
,shannavaS tseW eht ni raw eht ni noitca nees osla dah ajuP
!yadot retfa deniatretne eb lliw segnahcxe oN
.seilf worc eht sa sretemolik ytnewt tub saw nwotemoh sih taht nevig ,yllautca raf taht ton ,lleW
,teef evif tuoba fo tac hsiyerg A
.raw eht ot noitubirtnoc s'elpoep sih fo esuaceb emoclew saw eh erehw
.nioc a rof egnahcxe ni dlrowrednu eht ot sluos detraped deirref ohw
,demmirt yletalucammi erew
noitcepsni rof nwod sdraobpuc dna sdeb rieht yrrac ot enoyreve rof saw
,lluks sih tsniaga revahs eht fo snoitarbiv gnirraj-enob eht tlef ajaR sA
.noitanimoD fo raW eht ni seitilaer hsrah eht fo eno saw taht tub
,xytS reviR eht ssorca yenruoj laibrevorp eht ekiL
raewrednu sih hsaw ot gnirebmemer no ecivda citsaisuhtnerevo reH
.elif esraoc a dna
,ytilicaF gniniarT yratiliM cisaB
,sboj tniap ro eyd dedivorp osla yehT
.flesti ni lliks a eb ot devorp rennot-5 a sa nwonk kcurt eht otno gnitteG
.krowrepap rieht devol ymrA ehT
.ylgnivorppasid elzzum reh koohs ayaJ .srM
fo tuo ti ekam t’ndid eh fi tsael tA .sreciffo dna
,yldecrof dehgual dna delims stnaegreS
toof a fo ekacnap a nevE
.htaerb sih rednu gnirettum
.gniveileb eno teg ot tnemtsilne ekil gnihtoN
.detcepxe dah ajaR naht ylkciuq erom emac gninokcer fo yad ehT
.ymrA eht otni detpircsnoc er’yeht revenehw doom suoyoj a ni reve s’eno on
.noitidart ylimaf gnol a fo trap saw ymra eht fo trap a gnieb
.deggurhs rebrab ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,stiurcer eht fo tsom dna ,ajaR ekilnU
,erauqs edarap eht fo kcirb der eht otno gab leffud eussi-dradnats dna gab gnikih lanosrep nedalrevo sih htob deknolp ajaR
ajaR…halb ,halb ,halb ”,sroirepus etaidemmi rieht htiw pu ti gnirb dluoc seussi yna htiw sbuc“
.rof suomaf saw dnalsi yratilim eht sgnidliub yrots-evif sseltnuoc eht fo eno ot txen
,elgnuj fo sehcterts tsav hguorht delbmur kcurt ehT
,semarf rieht ot gnignilc
,draeh eb dluoc repsihw a toN
stnerap fo ssam eht ta kool tsal eno koot ajaR
,meht htiw kcurt eht ni deyats dah sOCN rehto owT
,dnalsi eht fo dne rehto eht ot meht ekat dluow taht skcurt eht sdrawot stiurcer rehto eht dna mih del sOCN eht sA
,gniM GS2 ma I ,noitamrofni ruoy roF“
,muirotidua na otni nwohs erew
.yb mih rebmemer ot ocserf sih flah evah dluow ylimaf sih
,ayaJ rM ,rehtaf s’ajaR
.suoivbo eht gnitats fo tibah a dah ehs timda ot dah ajaR
,retal setunim 02 toN
.yrtnuoC dlO eht ni kcab ymrA lanoitaN eht ni devres
egdirb erom saw ti taht tlef ajaR
.temleh s’enipucrop a htiw pu dedne ohw eno eht yvne t’ndid eH
.htuom sih tuhs noil eht tub
;esnet os eb t’ndluohs eH
.reyarp ni depsalc sfooh sih htiw
.waj rewol sih morf gnignah nekcihc fo eceip a ,ezorf ajaR
.tellaw sih gniward ,ajaR deksa
.nid eht revo tnaegreS-dn2 a delley
modeerf fo esnes gnitarogivni eht saw tI
.eson sih fo hctiwt a htiw naiJ dias
taht ton s’enam ym ,retsim ,no emoC“
.mih htiw paws a od ot elba saw ajaR taht
.etercnoc desopxe-ezeerb eht no neve gnorts erofeb emac ohw esoht fo raef eht
.daor eht ffo meht evohs ot troffe na ni meht gnihsur yb
pirg doog a gnivah fo noitanibmoc A
”stleP eht fo noitcerruseR“ GPROMM eht gniyalp fo shtnoM
lakcaj lateleks a
.sdaor eht no gnilcyc nehw stemleh elcycib no tup ot gnivah morf detpmexe seiceps wef eht fo eno erew snoil elaM
.ereh gnieb morf eno deraperp ylurt gnihton
,pu deffulf ruf sih htiw deyomaS a saw mih ssorca thgiR
.sgab eht nihtiw tae ot gnihtemos eb dluow ereht ebyaM .dooG
,seman ynam fo gnituohs eht yb ylno nekorb ssensuoires eht htiw
ajaR dlot dah ayaJ rM ,erofeb ruoh nA
stiurcer rehto eht fo raef fo tnecs eht
,spahrep dna ,citsimissep-reve eht roF
.yltnelis setalp eht dehceercs
.nap gniyrf eht retne ot emac nrut esohw esoht ot deussi srekcits htiw
.hguoc a htiw ajaR deganam
.tih gib a hcus erew snosirp dnalsi yhw ees ot gnitrats saw noil ehT
,noitareneg tnereffid a morf emac yllausu yeht taht tcaf eht tub
”!ikseR tnaegreS dr3 si ereh siht dna
.mih ediseb doots ohw naitaslA eht detacidni tac ehT
,elopgalf sti no hgih derettulf dnuorgkcab etihw a tsniaga tes
.gnaL naiJ s’eman yM“
,meht dniheb ylpmil gniggard sgab dna sliat
muminim a ot gnitegdif sih peek ot decrof saw
.enil derob a ni tes elzzum krad
.sretsop tnemtiurcer s’ymrA eht no deraeppa reven dah ayaJ
”?thgirla ,yaw ym no emmeL“ .ajaR dedaelp ”,gnol
,loohcS tedaC reciffO ot ti ekam ot
,dewollof yllautca eno on
.noitaluger yratilim gnihctam snoisnemid eht fo ecnalbmes a dehcaer ti litnu ruf ta kcah ot
,elbaraebnu tsomla saw raef fo tnecs eht ,ereH
skcarrab eht ni tfeht rof tnemhsinup eht dias ecno dah
”?hguod owt rof og em tel ll’uoY“
daeh s'noil nosmirc a ,galf etats ehT
:gniteerg yrotcidartnoc rehtar a htiw denozalbme
.raef fo repmihw ddo eht rof evas
”.ecalp dna emit rehtona rof detius tseb eb dluow taht hguoht ,uoy teem ot desaelp m’I yas dluow I“
ayaJ rehtaf s’ajaR
,llec s’eno morf desaeler gnieb retfa thgir
.aes ot tuo dnalsi na gnihsup taobgut a saw
.sraey rof moor sih gnieye neeb dah rehtorb regnuoy siH
emoh morf raf seirailixua sti tnes snamoR nrobfloW tneicnA ehT
.snoitidart lanoitan ruo fo eno s’tI
,am sih ot kaeps ot gnitnaw toN  !ysae tseR
.seloh fo riap gniralg a