.yrotsih ni nevorp selpmaxe ynam htiw
,selims dedraug ylluferac htiw ymra eht otni enog dah ynam woH
.syadkeew no sllac yna ekat t’nac I
.nettogrof eb ot srepsihw gnissap era emoS
,4SP sih gnisol
ajaR tsniaga denael naiJ
,lluf eht ot derab erew selkcah s’gniM tnaegreS
,dewehc eh sa delwocs regit gnuoy ehT
,ymrA eht si sihT .yssup yssenoil A“  .deneffits ajaR dna ,regit eht detrons ”,yssup a er’uoy leef I ,lleW“
,dnuora mih deppilf regit eht
,reciffo reerac a sa no gningis retfa
”?thgir ,pmac otni doof gnirb ot ton era stiurcer taht wonk od uoY“
.gnirtsward s’trohs sih htiw ytluciffid evah ot gnimees rettal eht htiw ,dnuora llits
,enil tnedifnoc a ni tes selzzuM
,shtap etarapes morf emoc dah ohw
”...raewrednu ruoy hsaw ot rebmemer dna
teef sih delffuhs ajaR ...retal
.stnerap sih htob dedulcni siht ,niryT roF
.dnefeD eW rehtegoT
,yenruoj siht fo gnirahs eht ni enola reve saw eno on taht wenk ajaR tub
,devom ekila gnuoy dna dlo ,mih tsaP
.noil egral eht delia tahw dootsrednu eh nehw don ot ylno gnisuap
noisserpxe s’ajaR fo edam eh tnemegdelwonkca ylno ehT
,yllacigolohcysp deraperp-lli saw eh taht timda ot dah eH
.esrow rof ro retteb rof
nootalp eht fo wor dnoces eht ni retto dewalc-llams eht taht deton ajaR
,ajaR ta rae na dekcoc naiJ
.won noil eht ot kaeps ot derad eno oN
,niryT .esruoc fO“
esrow semit net evarb yldalg dluow eh wenk ajaR tuB
,flow eht ot on yas reven dluoc noil eht tuB
,noil eht taps ”!seY“
sregnarts yb dednuorrus dna ,tihs ekil detaert gnieB
,ajaR erows ”!elohssa ,yrt uoy ees ot ekil ll’I“
!esle enoyreve erofeb ssenoil a mih llac ot derad tac eht tey dna
,gniM tnaegreS dednamed
!ssenoil a em dellac eH
.riapsed fo stnemom esoht lla thgir gnikam
.ylteiuq flow eht deksa
gniwollof stiurcer eht fo %5 pot eht htiw gnola
,naiJ‘ ?em dlot enim tahw wonk uoy diD“
,si taht—dlrow laer eht ni taht erus saw eH
noitan eht gnivres rof troppus sih lla roF
,ot detnaw eh esuaceb ylpmis srehto depleh eH
,taht tpecca t’nac uoy fI
,mih ot drager htiw devaheb ehs hcihw ni rennam eht ni tnetsisni eb dluoc rehtom sih ,eruS
.ekops eh erofeb htaerb a gnikat
.kcab ffuts fo selttob sih tog reven eH
,reedesuom suovren a tnorfnoc ot edam eh sA
.flesmih ssip ot tuoba dekool ohw
:noitpac a yb demarf
,seye yppup esoht dewohs eh nehw yllaicepse
.retal noitareneg enO
ekam ot dah yeht secifircas lanosrep ynam eht dezilaer yeht nehw dehsad meht evah ot ylno
naiJ htiw emit sih dna
,draeh eb dluoc woleb nwod tnaegreS eht fo luawretac ehT
?stisiv ffo-no fo sraey owt fo naps eht ni neve
?setam erutuf rieht rof sraey elohw owt tiaw ot tnaw dluow ynam woh rof
,esuohkooc eht ta nos rieht erofeb gnittis
.mih htiw hcuot ni yats ot detatiseh ajaR
.dedargnwod gnitteg fo epoh eht ni
.meht fo yteirav nwo rieht dah staC
,mih erofeb draobpuc bard eht ta deralg ajaR
.elbavigrofnu yllatot saw
,moorknub eht fo tuo derettucs retto ehT
,seohs-owt-ydoog a fo kool eht gnivah etipseD
,revo sgab rieht denrut enoyreve
sserttam eht no tlef eb dluoc erusserp A .mih fo tnorf ni ti od retteb d’yeht
.seye sih ni erutsiom fo tnih a ees dluoc ajaR ,nworf sih etipseD
,gnissuf reh lla htiw pleh hcum fo eb t’ndluow rehtom siH
srehto ynam eht nioj ot ffO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?siht si lleh eht tahw dnA“
,noisseccus kciuq ni sriats eht nwod nar noil dna flow ehT .delims ajaR
.rehtegot retnec noitpoda eht otni dekcehc yeht os
.laem tsal sih eta niryT erehw
”!tnaegreS ,seY“ ”?RAELC TAHT SI
.metsys AP eht revo reciffo na delworg
,eb reve dluoc enoyna sa etanutrof sa neeb dah eH
,sdrawkcab gnikcik deirt dna delggirw ajaR
,tnits htnom-9 sih gnitelpmoc retfa thgiR
,ti otni rotcaf t’ndid seiceps s’enO
,SCO ot detsop saw naiJ retfA
,drawrof deniart srae dna seye sih tpek eH
,deifisnetni sriatsnwod gnilley eht sa talf srae rieht
.elzzum sih no ekorb elims a dna
”.em gnissarrabme potS“
,floWisakiM yb ”snoS ot srehtaF“
,thgis lacimoc a neeb evah dluow tI
,remocwen eht ta eralg ot denrut ajaR
ksir gib a gnikat saw flow eht wenk ajaR
.ffo saw eh neht dnA
.wodniw eht fo tuo riahc ybraen a gniworht morf flesmih pots ot
”.peek ot eludehcs a evah eW
?rehtona dnif ot deen htom eht t’ndluow
,daeh sih fo tlit a htiw mih gninimaxe saw naiJ .naiJ saw tI
,latem detned tsniaga
.tseb sih tlef dna dekool eh erus ekam ot saw
.stuocs buc rof pmac yadiloh a ton
.llef ti erofeb sgnaf s’niryT fo s’eno morf gnuh nekcihc fo eceip A
,shtnom eseht lla neeb dah eh hsiloof woh ezilaer mih ekam ot hguone saw eman reh fo dnuos ehT
.gnihsulf srae sih htiw
”.noitces ruo ni kaerf lortnoc taht sa hcus ,ecaf thgim eh smelborp tahw mih llet t’ndid uoY“ .delims dna
,taht no desab TMB ni esruoc gniniart pihsredael eht otni detsop gnieb evresed yllaer eh diD
.did eh sa gnigagnesid
.noitidart ylimaf eht dlohpu ot detcepxe saw eh ,ylimaf sih fo elam a sa woH
.srehto morf parc htiw pu tup ot evah won ll’eh ,taerG
mrof sselenam sih dekcom dah gniM tnaegreS yaw eht tub
”?suoires gnikcuf uoy erA“
,spu-teem emaceb srehtegot-teG
.pmac ot yaw nwo ruoy ekam ll’uoy os ,won yob gib a er’uoy
.sllac derewsnanu fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.nworf a ni desaerc worb depirts siH
,wap rehto eht nO
.dah ylurt eh tahw mih wohs ot
”!ruf ruoy nettalf dnA“
.hgis a tuo gnittel
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
eludehcs ysub reh fo tuo emit eht koot ehs tuB“
.roirepus dna erovinrac htob erew uoy sselnu
.gniniart htiw erefretni ot snoitcartsid yna tnaw t’ndid eh sa ,reilrae noil eht detcatnoc t’ndah flow ehT
.ajaR tsrub ”!si ereht thgir nmaD“
.mih dennuts daeh sih fo mals rehtona tub
,gniM tnaegreS delley
.derac rehtom sih taht ton
.tnemtrapa sih ni rennid yrotarbelec a ot ajaR gnitivni yb detarbelec eh
erew retto dewalc-llams eht dna naiJ ylnO
.yttej railimaf-oot-lla eht fo hcterts gnidne-reven eht gniklaw lla
,ti gnittimda ekil t’ndid ajaR
.ylmlac naiJ deilper
.taht ekil gnihtyna ro ,yrtnuoc ot ytud fo esuaceb ylerem ton
.gniM tnaegreS dednamed
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     .esnopser ni
.edisa meht gnignilf ,delrans ajaR
.erauqs edarap eht sdrawot gninrut
,dekoj yeht ,dehgual yehT
,yromem dab a tsuj saw dneirflrig-xe siH
.did eh sa gniweks srae sih fo eno
.enoemos gniteem eb thgim I sa
.erauqs edarap eht ot nwod sroolf eerht draobpuc sselesu-won eht kcuhc ot ton lortnoc sih lla koot ti dna
.swalc dehtaehsnu htiw epiws tfiws a ti evag
,ygolohtna STACDLIW :SEICEPS dna raW fo sgoD eht ni deraeppa ylremrof evah ”snoS ot srehtaF“ .retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a
.spil sih no elims das a dah ohw
,yenoh ekil dekool tahw fo selttob citsalp thguorb dah raeb htols A
?’RIS‘“ ”—senohpllec aremac denoitnem ylno tsil ehT“
,dluoc eno tseb eht gniod dna
.elpoep fo sdnik ynam teem lliw uoy ,efil nI
,renetsil evitnetta na saw naiJ
.ot emoh nruter lliw uoy ylimaf gnivol ehT
,yap ot lleh fo gninraw
.devirra yeht litnu snoitisop pu-hsup ni eb won dluow stiurcer ehT
?mih rof saw ehs naem yllaer taht did tub ,tem eh ssenoil ylno eht saw anirlaS
,desuac evah thgim ehs tnemssarrabme eht etipsed tub
,rehtona devol ylurt eno fi ,lla retfA
.tnemom a no gnah esaelp
.taht tuoba yas ot gnihtemos tog ev’I nehw ton ,lleW
evitisop a gnivah fo seutriv eht gnillotxe
”.gnol ekat t’now sihT
.flesruoy tuoba nrael ot uoy rof ereht era srehto tuB
.mra s’ajaR gnigdun ,naiJ deksa
?yad tsrif ruoy no enituor gnag ruoy od erad uoY“
.pu swap sih gniworht ,ajaR dias ”!reh wonk t’nod uoY“
,mih kcom ot detnaw enoyna fI
.eman s’ajaR fo surohc eht yb dewollof
,hsifllehs fo snac lareves gnola thguorb dah
smrofinu ecivres evitcepser eht ni doots
.draobpuc sih ni kcab eson sih gnikcits erofeb
”!stiurcer rehto eht fo tnorf ni llA
”.gnorw og lliw gnihtoN
ecivres eht tfel gnivah ajaR htiw
,meht fo tser eht morf tuo flesmih delgnis tsuj dah eH
.spih sih naht regral hcum ton
.pmuj ot enoyreve gnisuac
rennab roloc-lluf a yb detnalppus
,stiurcer rehto eht fo yna naht rellams sezis ynaM
.mret sih detelpmoc eh nehw rotcartnoc seilppus yratilim a htiw boj a dnuof noil eht
slacisyhp lacidem rieht gniliaf ,metsys eht detaehc ohw seetsilne sseltnuoc erew erehT
,ti dellac dah rehtaf sih sa ,ronoH larutluC
,ralimis neve saw ecir nekcihc eht fo llems ehT
”?lla ti revo gnitteg melborP“ .naiJ devresbo
?decitonnu og ti evah ot ylno
,reweiv eht fo thgir eht sdrawot
,tuoba derac eh esoht fo troppus eht dah eh tub
ymrA eht edistuo dlrow eht
,niaga denrub eb ylbaborp dluow eH
.emalf gniyd a gnisahc htom a
.noonretfa eht rof meht eraps t’ndluoc yratiliM eht esuaceb lla
.htiw sdneirf eb reven dluoc eh
.mih ta nworht eb dluow taht gnihtyna ecaf ot egaruoc eht dah eh gniveileb
.tnecs s’ajaR ta gnihctiwt eson kcalb-laoc sih
,cisaB morf did yeht detaudarg tuB
.oga keew a tsuj yadhtrib ht02 sih gnihcaer retfa nam a gnieb mih tuoba reh dlot dah eh tahw kcab ekat t’ndluoc eh dna
.drawa ssentif dlog a htiw gniniart otni ti edam uoy taht duorp era I dna rehtaf ruoy taht
”?melborp ruoy s’kcuf eht tahw tsuJ
.lward dluow eh ,ajaR
,ylsuoiciv rekcol sih gnikcatta ,deraor ajaR
,reveirter nedlog regral raf a yfirret tac rellams eht ees ot
,moorknub suoicaps eht dnuora detarebrever hceercs ehT
wonk ot uoy tnaw I“
,esuohkooc ro skcarrab eht ni ecaps egdirf rof gnipoh saw eh fi derednow ylfeirb ajaR dna
.regit gnilrans a tub
?doog nwo sih rof neeb lla ti t’ndah
.meht erofeb ynam os yb desrevart neeb dah taht yenruoj A
?thgir ,tuoba lla saw secroF demrA eht tahw fo trap saw ytivisulcni ,yeh tuB
ruFikiW ro AF sih no seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
.gnisir tfel dah eh ruf elttil tahw
,sserttam derevocnu eht no ylivaeh nwod gnittiS
.secneirepxe nwo rieht erahs ot tif nees reven dah sevitaler nwo sih rof
,naiJ ta ecnalg a elots ajaR ”’.uoy evol I
,deneppah dah taht lla rof taht dezilaer ajaR ,noos dnA
.sesirprus fo lluf saw naiJ tuB
.siht otni mih gnittup rof dlrow eht ta yrgna
,rehtaf ruoy tuoba taht ees ton thgim uoY“
.rof epoh ot hcum oot saw
?tset ssentif tnemtsilne-erp sih rof drawa dlog a deveihca dah ohw noil eht
,TMB fo noitelpmoc
,tnemom gnol a rof ajaR ta derats niryT
.lortnoc rednu repmet ydoolb ruoy peek lliw uoy
.yttej deretlehs eht fo edahs eht rednu gnippets
,wap sih ni sregnif s’nos sih depsalc ajaR
”,ffo nos reh ees ot yaw eht lla emoc ot
ecnatsid eht otni ffo derats yeht
.gniniart rieht fo swol dna shgih eht gnirud rehto hcae gnitroppus
!ronoh ym detlusni egraS eht dnA
.elbissop emaceb gnihtyna
.tiurcer rodarbaL a deifiralc ”,riS ,oN“
.meht erofeb tuo stnetnoc eht gniruop
,sriatsnwod stiurcer fo hctab rehtona gnillirg gniM tnaegreS raeh dluoc eh ydaerlA
,god.ecioveht ta
”?taht lla tog uoy oS“
stneve suoutlumut dna regnarts etelpmoc a koot ti tub
.taorht s’regit eht ni werg elbmur A
!su morf yawa nekat rof drah dekrow ev’ew gnihtyreve dah tsuj eW“
,nekorb sesimorp dna staerht ,sthgif dna stnemeergasid eb dluow erehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”snoS ot srehtaF“   :yojne esaelP
.rekcol sih otni gab lanosrep ytpme-raen sih gnicalp erofeb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,kcab dloh ot elbanU
tnempiuqe deussi-non yna raew ot si eno oN
.enoyna ot wob dluow noil on tub
.tnemom a rof devom eno oN
.nwod eciov sih peek ot troffe on gnikam
”.did elohssA tnaegreS naht erom em dedeen uoy ekil dekool tI“
?UOY OT RECIFFO NA EKIL KOOL I OD“
.TMB ni emit rieht yojne ot eno gniwolla fo ecnahc tsethgils eht dah taht
,niaga noitces eht gnizidrapoej uoy hctac I fi ,raews I
,yamsid s’rehtaf sih ot ,ajaR
.nwod sroolf eerht eseht pmuj llew sa thgim I“
.ecnatcepxe tuohtiw ytisrevda morf ylno semoc egaruoc eurt rof
.egraS eht no dnal neve thgim I ?swonk ohW
.mih fo dloh thguac meht fo owt dna ,delley stiurceR
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT dna snoitacilbuP tenalPruF yb dehsilbup
,”teerts emas eht klaw yam sgnik owt oN“
,efil sih ni ybressap a ylerem saw dneirflrig siH
.denmad eb swal livic ,dnuorg eht otni teef xis tac eht depmuht evah dluow rodarbaL eht—
.mih ediseb tas regnellahc sih sa
.tsom eht dedeen saw ehs nehw mih tfel gnivah
.denihw rodarbaL eht
”.erauqs edarap eht ot troper dna stnerap ruoy ot eybdoog yas esaelp ,stiurcer llA“
.troppus reh rof gnipoh
.ecaps knalb otni gnirats ot koot daetsni dna ,sraet sih gnibbad pu nevig dah eH .ajaR derepsihw ”?ot
.enolabA evisnepxe gnidulcni
,edirp lanosrep tuoba wenk eh gnihtyreve tsniaga tnew pleh reh dedeen eh taht gnittimdA
,knilb sa hcum os dluoc noil eht erofeB
,meht htiw selbamusnoc dna skcans fo stnuoma suoreneg thguorb dah ,ajaR ekil ,ynaM
)GNISSIM( emiT tsaL  .ymrA eht ni emit s’floWisakiM yb deripsni saw yrots sihT .egap
raeb htols eht ot yaw sih gnikam erofeb tiurcer eht ot ”uoy gnihctaw eb ll’I“
tsrif eht hguorht enog ylno dah eh tuB
,srehto eht htiw elbmessa ot erauqs edarap eht ot nwod gniog ton
erom ecno ajaR devohs eH
,ereh eb llits t’ndluow ohw
,tenalPruF yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
,sepirts fo rebmun eht erehw
,ramukayaJ ajaR yllaer eh saW
,timda ot dah noil ehT
snoitaluger etipsed
!ereh er’uoy sa gnol sa
”?niryT llet ot gnihtemos evah uoy t’nod ,ajaR“
!flesmih ajuP tnioppasid uoY
.yenruoj emas eht ni ekatrap ot rehtegot gnimoc
,kcohs sih ni pu doots dah ruf siH
.flesmih dnif ot deen dluow eh ,tsrif tuB
.enihsnoom fo smrof rehto ro daem eb ylisae dluoc tub
.ssensselepoh tub gnihton tlef ajaR
,doots eh erehw morF
.gniod fo yaw a dah efil sa
.yvaN dna eciloP ,ecroF riA ,ymrA eht fo
.gnivres ni eciohc on dah yeht ecivres a rof denrocs eb oT
.yltfos naiJ dias
enil ynapmoC eht fo roolf dr3 eht dehcaer eh emit eht yb egar htiw gniltsirb saw eH
.nettor-flah taem eht tae ot dednetni ro
.swap sih otni ecaf sih decalp ,noil nworg a ,eh
noissessop yreve fo deveiler
!hcnul htiw enod saw I retfa thgir
.kriuq lanoitutitsnoc a fo esuaceb lliw sih tsniaga detpircsnoc gnieB .gnihtyreve
.seitivitca suoiverp rieht demuser dna derettacs setamknub eht fo tser ehT
emoh doohbuc sih morf tuo devom dah eh ,yltnecer ylnO
dah eH .riapsed fo dnalsi nekasrofdog siht no ot klat dluoc eh eno on dah eh
.htiw ti ecaf ot dneirf wen a htiw
.delworg-trons noil ehT
tsniaga yrgna tlef eH
,skaets depparw-knirhs thguorb dah nogard odomok a
”.uoy htiw reh was I“ .tuo detniop naiJ ”,serac am ruoy wonk htob ew tub
.rehtona ot ffatskooc fo noitareneg eno morf nwod dessap erew sepicer eht fi derednop ylfeirb ajaR dna
,’TNAEGRES‘ SA EM SSERDDA LLIW UOY
.tsol seno devol dna
dah nezitic elam yreve hturt eht ecaf ot hguone evarb gnieb
”,noiL rehtorB ,uoy gnirehtob gnihtemos s’ereht ekil kool uoY“
,tlep sih rednu ecneirepxe taht htiW
.sreerac nwo rieht tceffa thgim noitpursid a hcuS
,noil a fo sotohp eht ,ti nO .tesdnim
degasivne syawla dah eh
.mih morf gnitaname mlac fo esnes a
.buc a tpoda yeht detseggus naiJ nehw suovren yllaitini saw ajaR .tneserp eht saw
,noitan eht fo ecivres eht rof
,etuc taht dnuof syawla dah eh
.noihsucnip ydnas a ot ecnalbmes mih gnivig
.ecivres eht ni esle enoyreve erofeb tnempiuqe wen looc eht tuo tset ot teg did eh
,rehtona ot del
”.sedarmoc dednim-ekiL
?pmac htaed siht ot yaw nwo ym ekam ot hguone dlo ydaerla m’I wonk ehs
.knuj fo elip s’rodarbaL eht fo tuo pac gnipeels a ekil dekool tahw tuo gnillup
,esrow srettam ekam ot dnA
,tsiaw eht dnuora ajaR gnilkcaT
”?gnihtemos ro ytrap a gninnalp syug uoY“
.reirrab larutluc eht hguorht dnatsrednu t’ndid eh strap eht yfiralc ot gnippots
esoht dettifeb sa ytiot-ytioh sa gnieb SCO morf gniliah
”?’RIS‘ KCUF EHT TAHW
,stinu wen rieht ot detsop neht erew yehT
.sattednev rieht no doog ekam yam ohw
”,flesmih rof flow yreve t’nsi ti ,em oT“
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
suoredrum a derettum gniM tnaegreS
”,sriatsnwod elbmessa ot etal sa gnieb rof uoy hsinup ll’yeht ,wonk uoY“
,snoitibma dna sepoh rieht revo esnefed lanoitan koot yeht esuaceb t’nsaw lleh sa erus ti dna ,evres ot dah yeht tluaf rieht t’nsaw tI
”?ti tuoba klat ot tnaw uoY“
,rehtegot niht dna kciht hguorht tog flow eht dna eH
.uoy evol syawla lliw ew
.ecafrus latem looc eht tsniaga daeh sih fo edis eht gninnip
mih sdrawot emoc dluohs ohw
.ssenisub ruoy htiw no teg ,syuG
,ssem tneloiv a otni nwod gnikaerb erofeb ecivres yratilim sih fo—yad a flah ,on—
,ylniatrec anirlaS toN
.ecnednepedni s’aruP ecnis reve
gnakiaS ualuP no erots noisivorp a taht gniwonk
,yad taht emit tsrif eht roF
;gniyas a dah snoiL
2 fo 2 traP ,floWisakiM yb
.taorht sih deraelc ajaR .ylthgils kcab daeh sih gnilgna ,kcab rae na dekcoc niryT
.kcab sraey 72 noisserpxe nwo sih dehctam ti fi rednow tub pleh t’ndluoc ajaR dna
,reip etercnoc ot taob morf
.detrats sthgif teerts tsrif eht woh saw taht deveileb saw tI
.kaerb dnekeew ehT“
,edis sulp eht nO
.tlep s’ajaR tsniaga dexelf swalc nwo siH ”,hguot
?gniodnu sih rof nosaer yrev eht eh saw ro
deb rekced-elbuod sih fo tsop leets eht tsniaga drah swalc sih pmalc ot dah dna—
.htob naiJ dna mih degguh dna
.ereh emit ruoy yojnE .won oG
elims ylkcis a mih evag reilrae kcurt eht edisni dekcams dah eh lesaew ehT
,riahc sih morf pu tog regit eht
,yratilim eht htiw laed ot dah llits eH
.niryT delworg ”,aP ,wonk I“
,srehtaf gnuoy owt rof ysae t’nsaw tI
.draeh eb dluoc kcirb no kaets fo talps ehT
yaw eht yb ,esu ot dewolla t’nerew yeht tfil a dah hcihw—
.hgual erad ton did ajaR tub
.SCO fo daetsni tsilaicepS lacinhceT sa pu dedne
,gninraw tuohtiw dna
elttil degnahc dah tI
t’nseoD !od ot tahw em gnillet dna gnissuf syawla s’ehS“
,thgin ta em llac t’noD
.mih ta deralg ajaR  .naiJ deilper
,etuor taht gniog deredisnoc reven dah ajaR wohemoS
,sneppah revetahw taht rebmemer tuB
,yad a ni devlos eb reven dluoc smelborp fo tsetaerg ehT
.ezag s’regnellahc sih teem ot gnisufer
,lufpleh eb syawlA“
.noil a fo buc a naht erom gnihton saw eh raeh ot rehtaf sih rof od t’ndluow ti dna
,noitanimreted dna evol htiw tub
.revo dewob gnitteg tuohtiw evaw egareva eht dnatshtiw dluoc eh ekil kool t’ndid retto eht dna ,tfarcria wen ,keels esoht lla fo tipkcoc eht otni tif ylbissop t’ndluoc adnap ehT .lacimoc rehtar saw ti timda ot dah ajaR
,amolpid cinhcetylop sih htiw gnola
.dehtaerb eH ”?aP jaR ,ti si tahW“
.ylluferac ajaR dias
,detcepser eb ot saw enam s’eno taht snoil gnoma nwonk saw tI
,smoorknub rieht ot pu yaw rieht edam stiurcer eht fo tser eht dna ajaR ,noitcepsni smotsuc tnaegreS-2 eht retfA
,sweivretni boj rof pu nrut ot elba gnieb ton srekees-boj fo sesac erew erehT
”!niaga siht htiw uoy hctac em tel ton retteb uoY
,yratiliM eht saw siht tuB
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
flow eht dezilaer ajaR ,nwod peed
retto dewalc-llams dna regit ,adnap
,rehtegot efil fo sklaw lla morf elpoep thguorb noitpircsnoC
.deddon ylerem naiJ
.enoyreve gniltrats
.kcab sraey esoht lla gniniart sih gnirud renwod rojam a saw regit a fo kaerf lortnoc gniraebrevo na dna
.mih dniheb enoemos dias ”?ajaR“
”.doog nwo ruoy rof lla s’tI“
.wodniw eht edistuo yks eht ta ylsseldrow derats noil eht
.kcab gnihsur emac wenk eh gnihtyreve dna
,reh demalb eh yas etiuq t’ndluoc eH
,htob meht dnib gnidnatsrednu dna erac t’ndluow
,efil sih fo egnellahc tsetaerg eht ni won saw eH
enoemos saw siht wenk eh ,tnemom taht nI
”?—reilrae morf tihs eht naht ti ot erom s’ereht yleruS“
.esool llup ot gniyrt
.guht depirts siht morf eerf kaerb neve t’ndluoc eh tey dna ,noil a s’eH
.setad emaceb spu-teem dna
gniht enO  .decaf snoitalubirt dna slairt tuoba deklat dna
noil eht ta ylsuovren dekool
”?ecitsujni eht leef lla uoy t’noD
”.dekcohs m’I“ .naiJ delggig
.naiJ tem eh taht tnaem ti fi
,mih sdrawot denrut niryT
.shtnom rof mih morf raeh t’ndid eh dna
.srae sih fo gniweks eht saw
.regit regnuoy a ot flow redlo na dias
,sroirepus ruoy tuoba dab klat t’nod
.denraw neeb ev’uoY“
”.neht uoy tem evah ton thgim I“
esoht fo dnuoba erew sromuR
.taht lla dna serutsap reneerg tuoba lla syawla saw ehs rof
”.retaw fo luftekcub a htiw uoy nword ll’I
,floWisakiM yb snoS ot srehtaF“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ylprahs ikseR tnaegreS dednammoc
.redwop eeffoc dna ykrej feeb fo smargolik ruof htiw gnola
,setamknub decidujerp htiw laed ot gnivaH
,ereh er’uoy sa gnol sa tuB“
,edis sih tsniaga deppals gab regnessem kcalb siH
snoitareneg ynam yb detnuomrus dna devarb neeb dah hcihw
,stnaegreS eht ot potpal gnimag dna enohPI ,daPI
,lortnoc-fles dah evah dluoc eh deveileb dah ajaR
.lla retfa ,htaerb dab rof noitatuper a dah sodomoK
?revo lortnoc on dah yeht gnihtemos fo esuaceb evol rieht tsol dah stpircsnoc fo snoitareneg ynam woH
?tihs dna samajap nwo ruoy raew ot dewolla era uoy taht kniht uoy diD“
,sraey eseht lla retfa neve
elbat eht revo dehcaer neht
etam sih delzzun ajaR
kcab swalc sih desae ajaR
.did eh sa gnilbmuts
”.em rof detiaw evah t’ndluohs uoY“
.dekcik eh sa tuo swalctoof
.yojne ot demees sgod stellep yrd eht fo skcap lareves erew mih erofeB
drawrof kool ot ereht si tahw ,naiJ ,em llet ,oS“
”.desaelp naht erom eb dluow srehto ehT
.tseretni htiw ti gniziniturcs ,snac eht fo eno pu dekcip gniM tnaegreS
.derudne dah eh tahw etipsed
.meht ot rewsna t’ndid eh tsael ta tub
mih no gnikcehc dna gnissuf taht llA
sdeb rekced-elbuod 8 fo moorknub emas eht ot detsop neeb dah ohw ,retto ehT
,ni knis ot sdrow esoht rof etunim lluf a koot tI
.lla retfa mih rof tuo dekrow yllautneve sgniht
,tnemtsilne sih erofeb keew a sraef sih tuoba anirlaS dneirflrig sih ot gnikaeps deirt
.dlofowt ezis sih gnisaercni
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.ereh neeb d’eh tsal eht ecnis
.nwod mih gnidloh swap eht fo eerf kaerb ot gniyrt ,ajaR delrans
sreksihw ym denaelc neve ehS
#  .erofeb emac ohw esoht fo
.sriatsnwod elbmessa ot tfel ydaerla dah setamknub eht fo tsom taht was ajaR ,mih dniheB
”?ta gniyalp er’uoy kcuf ehT“
,sdap wap sih hguorht tuo gnipees ssenpmad eht tlef eH
.htiw elbatrofmoc saw eh enoemos saw
.htiw deussi neeb dah eh strohs kcalb dna trihs neerg eht otni ylwols degnahc dna
,stnerap sih morf ecaf sih gnitrevA
,edarit s’ajaR fo elohw eht tuohguorht tnelis saw naiJ
.regit eht dednamed
.dednammoc dah tnaegreS eht tahw od ot flow eht llet ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc eh wohemos tub
.tihsyerp fo daol elohw A
.paehc t’nsaw ffuts tahT
,euc no fi sa nehT
.tsrif detnuoc srats dna stserc ,srab
.tihsyerp fo erahs nwo sti tuohtiw saw efil fo elcric eht dias eno on ,yeh tub
.desirprus t’nsaw ajaR
.ti fo dnuos eht yb ,raeb A
.roirp sraey ruof ylno
,erew yeht ereh dnA
.elcyc raey-owt rieht fo dne eht llit niamer dluow yeht erehw
.ekam reve dluoc tiurcer a ekatsim tsetaerg eht
,tsrow eht deraf dah ajaR
,tnemtsilne sih ot pu gnidael shtnom eht nI
,srehto revo drol won dluoc ohw
,ajaR sdrawot decamirg eH .detrons naiJ
,dehsams neeb dah draobngis cinortcele ehT
.etam erutuf sih fo ssol ehT
.draobpuc leets detcapmi dna dehctarcs yldab eht tsniaga mih demmals regit eht
,neht 62 ylno erew yehT
,yawa denrub dah emalf eht retfa nevE
”?faed dna dnilb htob uoy erA“