.pmaws eht fo edis rehto eht derettil
,pot eht revo dna sllih eht hguorht ,daor eht wolloF
,efil ni egnahc a rof gniksa
,ycnuob dna tfos ,hcuot ot yoj a saw loow siH .pihsnoinapmoc
sepahs dnomaid wolley htiw kcalb saw eH
.dega-rednu saw ehs nehw neve
,cinap flesmih tlef naitsabeS
.raef htiw detarbiv ydob eritne sih dna koohs sgel sih
,ydob gnileef enilucsam erom hcum sih
was dna noitcelfer sih ees ot ,nwod dekool eH
,ydob wen sih erutcip tuoba tsuj dluoc eH
.ti fo emit reisae na evah d’eh erus saw eh ,t’nsaw eh gnihtemos eb
,yllanretni dekcinap eH .dnilb
drofwalC ecilA yb
.yawa kcab ot dellepmoc oot raf tlef eh tey dna
.erus lla ta t’nsaw yltsenoh naitsabeS
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.eciohc rehto on dah eh esuaceb ylno ni deyats dah eh ecalp a
,llih peets a nwod saw revir ehT
,rehtien ro ,yug a ,lrig a tcartta dluoc eH
.evael ot deen I yhw s’taht ,dluoc I“
gnieb desilivic a saw eh
.efil retteb a ot epacse na rof paehc emac ecirp eht os dna regnad on esnes dluow eh
seye sih ni sraet htiw ekans eht gniknaht
,tnereffid saw tI
.lla ta redips a gnieb fo laeppa eht dnif t’ndid yllaer eh
saw noitcelfer eht ni kcoc sih ees tsuj dluoc eh dna
dah rO ?gnihtemos htiw detcefni eh saW
gnihtemos tlef eh
.desahpnu yletelpmoc ,redips eht ta derats seye eulb reh dna
.ylerus tub ylwols
,deppir ,enod eb thgim sehtolc siH
.pirg dluoc taht sregnif fo sderdnuh ekil gnitca sriah ynit fo daetsni
.tsol ton evah ot dalg saw eh doohnam a htiw gnola
”.gnihtemos ro seenk sehctib eht saw eh gnikniht
,dnilb neve ,neht desilaer eh ,kcoc sih gnihcuot nI
.syawhtap eht no dnuorg eht ssorca gniklaw naht reisae saw ecalp ot ecalp morf gnibmilc tnaem
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.eman dlo sih ot refer dna pu pils flesmih tlef tsomla eh ,ydaerlA
a ro deppans taht sgel niht ,seye ynam oot htiw erutaerc yracs a eh saw regnol oN
.neetneves saw ehs nehw lohocla dlos erus ehs tub ,gnuoy saw ehs tslihw knard reven ehs
,cifirroh saw hcnets ehT
.yawyna no sehtolc htiw did eh sa cifirroh sa tsuj dekool eh sa
mih no espalloc ot denetaerht htob dna
,htuom sih hguorht dessih egdulS ”?ti si ohW“
,lenparhs eht dehcuot eh nehw ,oS
,ynit erew silopomsoC ni sesuoH
.won morf gnitrats ,trats wen a
.elbanigami hsart fo sdnik lla htiw dellif saw dna
,xam eht ot detset saw noitisopsid suovren ydaerla siH
.deciton t’ndah eh taht ecnaraeppa sih ni egnahc eht yb ni nekat dna dekcohs oot
,enog saw noisiv sih ,nehT
.won revir a naht liart ygduls a fo erom saw ti sa ,revir eht raen gnieb dekil ydoboN
.mih revo lla niap fo selkcirp tlef naitsabeS ,tuo gniyrC
,ydaets ma I litnu tiaW
.dnah a gnisiar dna dnuora gninrut ,sredluohs reh deggurhs mussopo ehT ”.lla si ,od ot gnikniht emos tog …tsuj I ,haeY“
.no dloh ot lladnaR dlot dna pu dekcab eh
,teerts reteiuq a no saw eH
.sinep sih no deknay eh sa
.eman wen a ,trats wen a
.uoy rebmemer t’nod I
,drofwalC ecilA yb
.hctarcs ot deunitnoc eh sa truh ot gninnigeb niks sih
,yawa og t’ndluow taht hcti nA
ytic eht edistuo tsuj nar tI
.yawa gniyrrucs meht dnes dna ffo lamina yna tup ot hguone
,erofeb evah t’ndid eh gnihtemos
,erongi ot taerg oot ytisoiruc sih
daeh sih no snroh delruc kciht owt ,mar a
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,htgnel sih nwod dna tils eht morf tuo elkcirt dees sih hctaw ot ,enodnu emoc flesmih ees ot
,ytic tsesolc txen ruoy si esulceR“
,efil wen a dedeen eH
,mih ot gnikcolf elpoep
.ot tnaw t’ndid ro ,evael t’ndluoc ohw elpoep htiw detalupoprevo yleritne gnimoceb noos
?em htiw gnorw si lleh eht tahW
.efil sih fo tser eht rof ylbaborp silopomsoC ni kcuts ,ti htiw evil ot gnivah saw eh dna
!eurt emoc dah hsiw siH
,ffo taeh eht fo emos evats ot gnipoh
,tsam lluf ta saw hself siH
imoaN tub ,suoivbo saw ti thguoht t’ndah eH
.seye ynam sih ot serats latnemegduj ylno
,mih ot gnillac saw gnihtemoS
.stekcop sih morf dluoc eh tahw barg ot thguohterof eht dah eh tub
,ylsuoiverp seye ynam os gnitrops retfa noisiv fo dleif wol a hcus evah ot
.ybraen top a otni ti deppord dna
,em ot pu gnirauqs deirt eh nehw gnihsal a esra sih evag nosraL .slrig ym fo eno ot kcid sih tuo gnignirb rof tuo kcirp a kcik ot daH“
.ti dnuora emoh reh tliub dna
.ta neeb dah eh level eht ot kcab mih gnirb
.elbaraebnu yletulosba emaceb noos ti litnU
,suoegrog dna htooms saw ecaf kcalb siH
,daerD rof seirots trohs etorw ohw
.regnad rof gnitsat dna tuo gnirekcilf eugnot sih
,droffa dluoc wef yrev yruxul a saw ecaps gniviL
.teiuq dna ecaep emos rof revir eht rof dedaeh
,denifer erom hcum saw gniraeh fo esnes siH .eson nottub
,tuh pu nekorb eht fo rood eht no dekconk lladnaR
,ytip fles ni gniwollaw saw eh sA
lladnaR sa trats wen sih saw sihT
.erofeb naht esrow knits eht tuoba thguorb ti ,did ti nehw dna
.tawt a t’nerew dna selur eht dewollof yeht gnol os enoyna democlew ehs taht dna
,trap tsom eht rof emirc dna ytrevop ni denword ytic a saw silopomsoC
.tuo ydob ekans eritne sih gnignirb
,skool sih nevig taht detcepxe eh
.egnahc tseggib eht saw ecaf siH
,dnuor dna ecin saw daeh eht dna
teef dna sdnah siH
.ereh fo tuo teg ot deen I .lladnaR m’I“
.noitarepsed rieht ni tuo ekorb ecneloiv os dna
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.srae evitisnes wen sih hguorht gnidnuoser ssih a
,taht tsuj did mar ehT
,hsiw sih otni evag ti
,huH ”.dnim ruoy no sgniht wef a tog uoy ekil kool uoy tub
dna detniuqs naitsabeS
.revir eht nwod kert sih ekam ot nageb dna
,ti droffa t’ndluoc ylpmis tsoM
,ydob gnol a dah ohw
,dnim ot mees t’ndid eH
.derevoc ti tog sah nosraL
nevig neeb won sah eh efil wen eht etaicerppa ot
semit lareves flesmih gnipmup
.ydob kcalb knalb
,meht tcetorp ot no ksam a tuohtiw esuoh eht tfel reven elpoep ynaM
.yldetcepxenu ti tsniaga gnikcalc fooh sih ,hguor
.rettal eht rof og ot hguone citsimitpo gnileef t’nsaw eH
,eerf eb ot ton siht detcepxe evah dluohs eh …lleW
.desaelp eh revemohw htiw elgnim yllanif ot dna
,gniworg saw taht ytic a ni gnivil fo
,ni ti dekcus ehS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.wonk ot dedeen eH .gnignahc efil gnihtemos eb dluoc ti
.redduhs dna ekahs sgel sih tlef eh sa
.mih no etuc dekool erus saw eh
.ssecorp eht ni yticixot eht yb desiropav gnieb ro gniyd ton wohemos
,ssorca ti ekam ot ekans eht rof setunim erem koot tI
.detekcor yteixna sih dna ti ekil t’ndid eH
,ylkciuq dnah sih werdhtiw eH .PAZ
.ti devresed ohw rebmem devol hcum a
.detsisrep eh tub
,ereht tsomla thguoht eht ,nwod dekool eH
,egdulS fo sekil eht rof pirt elpmis a saw tI
.loow dna erugif gnizama na dleh ohw
,etagitsevni ot nwod gnidneB
.sesion dirroh dekraps dna nwod tohs tog ngis noen a nehw ot ralimis yrev dednuos tI
”hsipeehS gnileeF“   :yojne esaelP
hcum sgniht mraw t’ndid sremmus eht neve nehw
.ylevitarapmoc tnemtrapmoc ynit a redisnoc dluow seitic rehto tsom talf a ni gnivil sevlesmeht dnif dna
!mih evol dluow elpoeP
,ytic eht fo egde eht ot yaw sih edam eh sa ylluferac daert dna luferac eb ot dah naitsabeS
.yb og ot hcuot sih ylno dah eh enog noisiv sih htiw
,elbissopmi raen emaceb sehtolc rof gnippohs nehw sllafnwod sti dah ylniatrec redips a gnieb ,noitnem ot toN
?kcab mih gnidloh gniht ylno ehT
…ees dluoc eh tub
gnipeew dna gnikael
.kcab mih dleh skool sih taht detah eh dna
.mraw os ho tlef eh dna
,ti ees ot seye sih nepo ot kciuq saw eH
.doog on did ti tub
.edam tcejbo eht esion duol eht yb desirprus
.hguorht uoy tel ll’I yhw s’tahT .uoy ekil I
,evael dneirf sih dehctaw eh sa
”.esulceR dnif ll’uoy
!ti desilaer neve t’ndah eh dna
ecalp eht denwo ehs ,no sraey net ,woN
.steerts krad eht dellevart eh sa
?saw eh ohw rof mih gnitpecca esle erehwyna rof evah eh did ecnahc tahw
,elbahcaorppa erom dna reildneirf tlef ecaf sih
,tnorf ni bmil a devaw dna detnap eH
,revir eht pu rehtruf saw tI
,ytsan denrut noitalupop eht sA
.esir ot nigeb erutarepmet ydob sih tlef eh sa ti rof gnikool
psarg sih ni mrif saw tI
.tsal rieht eb dna yldaed eb dluoc htaerb eno taht niatrec
,flesmih llems osla dluoc eH
.daeh eht gnola fooh sih fo bmuht eht dellor yltneg
…emahs a eb dluow tI“ ”.esaelP
,nees erofeb reven dah eh taht ytuaeb fo gniht a
,yawa dekcab yeht
,hguoht knird a rof emoclew er’uoY
,elpoep deracs taht sgel gnol erom on
.emaceb eh deticxe erom eht ,flesmih gnileef saw eh erom eht
,owt ylno dah eh ,emit sihT
,nwod knirhs ot nageb ylneddus sgel sih
)?yaw taht nrob t’nsaw eh ylerus( margatnep
.mih ekil tsaeb a rof gnittif saw ereht tsael ta esuaceb deniamer dna
,stnap sa tuo emac shtaerb siH
ti ssorc ot deirt dah ohw stsaeb fo senob
.ot tnaw uoy fi ylno ,haN“
.thgilyad was reven ytic eht ni steerts eht fo ynam taht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.emit
.naitsabeS htiw now rehtom sih tub
.dloc syawla erew
,eromyna fo draehnu ton erew sredrum
.roolf eht ot gnippird dna
,hpmH“ .enon gnidnif tub ,eil a tceted ot gniyrt ,eugnot sih derekcilf egdulS ”?em pleh uoy naC
,hsiw sih derewsna dna ecaps morf emoc dah dehcuot dah eh revetahW
”?yedips ,erehwemos gnioG“
.yawa dessap renwo suoiverp eht ecno ecalp eht detirehni neht
,dluoc eh fi ynam yb devol eb ot detnaw
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,ecaf sih no elims a htiW
,drofwalC ecilA yb
”.ecin llems uoy esuaceb paehc s’tI“
.noitalupop ni gniworg esaec t’ndluoc tey
.edistuo teg dna sdworc eht morf yawa teg ot detnaw tsuj eH
,eno suoiverp sih ekil ekips a t’nsaw dna
.pu doots eh erofeb ,owt ro etunim a rof ,ereht yal eH .duorp saw eh
,dekcatta gnieb fo raef rof dehtolc nialp gnikrow ynam
,dnim sih otni tperc tbuod fles neddus dna redduhs A
.rekciht gniworg dna gninetrohs
.gniyd erew ehs fi sa
?suoivbo taht yllaer ti saw
rehtegot esolc os dna yldrazahpah os tliub sgnidliub eht
,degdelwonkca eb ot detnaw tsuj eH
.setunim nihtiw deticxe erom dna erom gnitteg flesmih leef dluoc eh ydaerla dna dloh ot recin ti gnikam
gnihcterts niks sih fo selkcirp eht leef llits dluoc eh tub
won thgir ,revewoH
,gnihton eb dluoc tI
.ysatsce ni tuo deirc eh sa dnah rehto sih ni ti htiw elddif tub pleh t’ndluoc eh
,srehto naht retteb erew syad emoS
,neddih sgniht gnipeek fo loot ydnah a saw loow siH
”hsipeehS gnileeF“ saw sihT
,won tsaeb a t’nsaw eh tuB
.epacsdnal yggos ydaerla eht no niar nwod gnirb ot gninetaerht dna kcalb erew sduolc ehT
.revir kcalb eht tsniaga noitcelfer sih dettops eh litnu
.revo mih gninokceb saw gnihtemos
,dnuora denrut eH
.skool sih dna ecnedifnoc siH
.yb esolc naeco eht sdrawot ylhtooms tahwemos gninnur
ti no peels dluoc uoy yfmoc os loow gninihs etihw htiw snroh evisserpmi htiw
,dooh ym no bmilc neht
.lla ta stekcop esoht otni gnihtyna tif dluoc ehs dezama saw naitsabeS ,erew sehtolc reh thgit woh htiW .tekcop reh morf gic-e na tuo thguorb ehs sa redluohs reh gurhs ot demees imoaN
.niap tuohtiw ton tub
!ffo wohs ot detnaw eh dliub a
.ffo pils ot lladnaR gniwolla dna nwod flesmih gnippord
.ssenwen siht htiw rehtona etartenep ot ekil eb dluow ti tahw enigami ot detnaw dna
.tsaf dleh lladnaR tub
.deppots eH ”-s’ti ,yeH“
.elbanigami raeg tsekciht eht otni dettif erew yeht ro
:gnol os rof deined neeb dah eh tahw deriuqer tsuj ylpmis eh
sserP tuotS retsiniS yb eniZ rorroH yrruF a
,eman fo eciohc s’rehtaf siH .lladnaR
hcae bmuht llams a dna sevooh owt dah
.tuo meht ssot d’ehs ,enil fo tuo tnew enoemos tnemom ehT
,tneps ylrettu saw eH
,fo duorp saw eh ydob a dah yllanif eH
elbaroda srae gnol sih
,nwod tas eh sa koohs sgel siH
.gnieb emit eht rof
,sgnidliub fo sllaw eht tsniaga bmilc dluow eh emit eht fo tsoM
,dnapxe ot elbanu neeb dah silopomsoC nosaer elos eht saw tI
,pu gninrub saw eh ekil tlef naitsabeS
.taht ta eno dedeen hcum a
.deraeppasid dah tcejbo eht dnuof eh
,flesmih ta gnikool pots t’ndluoc eH
.yawa gnilwarps mih tnes tsomla htaed dna yaced fo hcnets eht sa raf siht erutnev ot detnaw reve ydobon dna
ees ot daeh sih denrut naitsabeS
.duorp htob meht od dluow eH
luof os saw llems eht dna hcuot ot suoregnad ylbissop ,cixot saw ti hcum os detullop saw tI
,dekcohs t’nsaw eH
.flesti eldnah dna tor ot ti tfel dna nwot trop eht fo lortnoc tsol sreciffo ecilop
.stsaerb reh derevoc ylerab taht trihs kcen v a dna strohs rehtael thgit reh ni gnidnats
.yks eht morf nellaf dah ti ekil dnuorg eht otni gud
,egnahc ot gninnigeb saw mrof sih saw
,seirrebeulb fo tlems tI
,yenom eht dedeen ehS
ytic eht gnipolevne noos llems eht
,htworg taht htiw pu hctac ton dluoc tub
.ti ot esolc eb dluoc ydobon
,thgil elttil saw ereht taht nevig ,ees ot drah saw tI
,loow esraoc ekil tlef tahw ni derevoc tslihw
.regae dna yreppils
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.krow ot kcab dna rab reh ot kcab thgir gnidaeh
.redips tnaig a dnuora ysaenu
,daeh sih ni ti erutcip dluoc eH
.naitsabeS fo htaed eht dna mar eht
dewolley arelcs reh dna reh dniheb gniliart liat ekil-tar reh
,tuo dekop mih fo ezis eht tuoba daeh egral a dna denepo saw tI
!erofeb ti tlef reven d’eH
dnah defooh sih gnirevoc
,ylluferac dna sinep sih depsarg eh sa denaom eh ,llits dnilB
dnim ni laog on gnivah ,gnola gnirednaem ylerem saw eH
,tuo ydob elohw sih htiW .wolley ni osla
,sseltops ,etihw saw eH
,ytic eht morf yawa
,pleh rof yrc sih gniraeh
.mussopo na rof ,yhtlaeh dekool ehs dna taht dewohs ylniatrec erutsop reh ,t’nsaw ehS
,ydob suoegrog wen sih nopu ezag ot
,no saw eh revir eht fo edis eht no saw tcejbo gninihs eht taht evah dluow kcuL
.silopomsoC fo gnihton meht lleT
,ydob sih gnola lla dehcuot sevooh siH
.devol eb ot ,dekcuf eb ot
rehtegot esolc os gnieb sgnidliub ehT
.yrebbols dna tew ,gnol saw taht eugnot a
,dekrej eH .tcefrep
.ecaf sih no elims ediw a hcus dah eh tey dna
a saw dooh sih no dna
,doog eb dluohs eW
tfos lautca na osla dna slirtson
,gniees saw eh tahw eveileb yldrah dluoc eH
,tfel erew meht fo ruoF
.kcid wen sih depmup ylregae eh sa xes fo tnecs nwo sih
erac t’ndid eh tub
,dehtolcnu yletelpmoc saw eH
,tuo werg ruf siH
,mih gnihcuot rehtona denigami eh
.niaga ees ot thguoht reven d’eh ruoloc a
detullop os saw ti esuaceb saw ti fi erus t’nsaw naitsabeS
.revir eht gnissorc tuohtiw ereht hcaer ot elba eb d’eh erus neve t’nsaw eh
.shtnom fo tsedloc eht ni mraw mih peek dluow taht loow kciht dna
.tnereffid gnihtemos ,nehT
.desingocer eh eciov a
enob ekil hguor ,digir saw tI
,mar a saw eh ,woN
.ecaps sti gnidavni rof reh ta dessih taht tac kcalb a derongi dna
,selaT dnuoB yb oirotagrruP dna
;detartenep eb ot rO
.ees t’ndluoc eh saw ti tahw tub
yb esolc llaw eht tsniaga nael ot gnivom
.loow sih ot sknaht sselpot efil sih enigami dluow eh tub
.sa mih ot derrefer srehto tahw ro mih dellac srehto tahw rof erac on dah tub ,eman laer sih evig ot desufer eH
,nwod dekool eh nehW
,tuo ssap dluoc eh dab os tsomla saw ,revewoh ,hcnets ehT.efil
,resolc tog eh sa yteixna htiw deredduhs ydob sih
.egaugnal ydob s'ydobyna gnidaer ta doog saw
.woleb nwod revir eht fo noitcelfer kcalb eht tsniaga thgirb ylneddus saw taht ruoloc ymaerc a gnimoceb dna ruoloc gnignahc
”.ni elbatrofmoc leef I ecalp ylno eht s’tI
.ecalp wen a ot teg ot deen I
.dab t’nsaw tnereffid tub
.ti rof dereffus eh sa neve
esilaer t’ndid naitsabeS tahW
,ti leef dluoc eH
,yadot ffo yad eht dah eh tub
,efil sih ot mood lleps dna llih eht nwod llaf ton ot ylluferaC
skcoldaerd eulb dna elprup dah ehS
.esle gnihtemos tlef eh
.drawrof devom naitsabeS
elims a pleh t’ndluoc redips ehT
,dnuora llits erew ecilop ehT
.mih rof reirrab a ton saw redneg
,nosrep wen a saw eH
,flesmih evol dna daol sih esool tel ot
esle erehwyna detpecca eb ton dluow
”?imoaN ,rab ruoy fo tuo uoy sgnirb tahW“
!ti rof etarepsed flesmih tlef eh
.seye reh gnillor ,dnuorg eht no taps mussopo ehT
,mrof sih otni debrosba dah eh noitcocnoc revetahw yb delyts fi sa
,rebmemer dluoc ehs sa gnol sa rof rednetrab a gnieb ,ot deniart neeb d’ehS
?loow rieht ot sknaht gnihtolc deen neve peehs did tub
.etagitsevni ot devom eh dna
?thginot pleh rof dnuora kcits ot em tnaw uoy oD ?huh ,rehtaerb A“
.flesmih llik ro niur ton ot luferac yrev eb ot dah tsuj eh ,ssorca yaw a saw erehT
.wollef ylenol rehtar a saw naitsabeS
.mih ot neppah dluoc gniht lufrednow a hcus taht eveileb ot elbanu
.no evil dna ereh tegroF .og woN“
.sevlesmeht no espalloc ot ydaer erew dna yllej sgel sih
ffulf gniyrrac saw eh
.neeb dah syawla eh xes emas eht yletinifed yrev saw
,mussopo na saw tI
.gnieb emit eht rof ,ti derongi eH
.rettam ecaps ro ,lenparhs dnuor fo eceip a ekil skool taht tcejbo llams A
.deciton redips eht
,ecivres terces a ylbaborp saw sihT
,esle gnihtemos ro ,esiw pihsdneirf
secnahc sih ekat dluow eh ,llitS
.doog dna llew lla saw gnihtyreve ton ,lleW
”.esruoc fo ,dlog net roF
”.ereh netae teg dluoc uoy …etihw dna tfoS
.niks erom dna ruf ssel ecaf sih dna
!lufituaeb tlef eH
.dnaskciuq ekil dekrow ytic eht edistuo dum eht
.flesreh delaever dna thgil noen eulb a htaeneb deppets ohw
!emoceb dah eh erutaerc lufituaeb a tahw
,eroc sih ot mih ekirts dluow ti ,srehtO
,nosrep dab a ton er’uoy ;noitalsnarT
arboc eht rof dlog net derucorp eh ,elbuort hcum oot tuohtiw dna
,eh sa egnarts sa tsuj demees ehS
,sregnif defooh sih neewteb ereht kcid kciht kcalb a dna hctorc deloow sih was eh ,nwod gnikooL
,saw eh ohw rof mih tpecca t’ndluoc silopomsoC fI
,sredluohs reh deggurhs imoaN
,nwo sih llac dluoc eh mrof wen elohw a htiw ,flesmih ni ecnedifnoc deniag dah eh
.edis eht ot elkniwt a
.kcab lruc ot demees dna
.fles eritne sih gnirevoc
,enon gnidnif tub ,yhtapme gnikees dna ylenol traeh sih
,mih htaeneb lleh morf gob eht htiw ,yltnerruc evitisop a toN
,tuo saw eugnot siH
.regnol gnimoceb dna dnuor ssel gnimoceb ecaf sih
.kcab gninrut deredisnoc eh ,elihw a roF
.kool a ekat ot segadneppa ynam sih fo eno tuo dehcaer
,dessik eb ot ,degguh eb ot
”.dessip teg ot deen uoy fi ma I erehw wonk uoy ,tseug ym eB“
,mih niur ylno dluow taht ecalp a rof doog oot tlef eH
yraerd dna krad os syawla saw aera eht esuaceb fi ro
sesimorpmoc ekam ot dah dah hcir eht neve
.reveostahw ecnereffid on edam ti ekil tlef ti ,dehctarcs eh sa nevE
.retteb hcum ton saw edistuo ,tuo snruT
.esruoc fo ,knird eerf a teg I sa gnol oS
.noitamrofsnart sih gnileef morf saw eh no denrut woh
,mrofsnart dluoc eh fI
neeb reve d’eh naht rehtruf saw sihT
.meht htiw eno gnimoceb dna
dah eh leef ot eson sih ot - fooh a won - dnah a tup eH
.denethgieh ylno dah llems fo esnes sih tub
,dehcuot gnieb enigami ot ,hO
”.lladnaR ,kcul dooG
,secalp tsom ni depmarc flesmih dnuof dna egral rehtar saw eh ,gnihtyna yub ot evisnepxe saw ti
ytilaer das eht tsuj saw sihT
,edis rehto eht no kool ot dekil eh esuaceb ereh emac naitsabeS
.retaw hguorht gnimmiws erew eh fi sa
.emoclewnu rehtar flesmih dnuof eh silopomsoC ni neve tub
!sseldne erew saedi eht
htgnel sih gnikorts
,sgel sih neewteb gnihtemos leef dluoc eH
.yleritne gniraeppasid emos
.mrof ni egnahc a
,dnuora denrut eh sa mih dlot egdulS
!evila mih gninrub saw taht ylleb sih ni erif a
,lladnaR dehcuot pord a toN
.revir eht otni flesmih gniworht deredisnoc ylsuoires dna erif no saw eh ekil tlef eH
,saw ti tahw ot sa kool doog a teg ot mih rof yawa raf oot saw tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
?tluser eht saw siht dna ydob sih otni delwarc gnihtemos
.denifnoc gnileef tuohtiw gnol oot rof emoh sih ni pu depuoc niamer t’ndluoc eh ,revewoH
.daeh sih fo esab eht ta gniworg
,esrow nettog dna denepmad evah ot demees noisiv thgin siH
,eromyna was reve ytic siht thgil fo ecruos ylno eht erew sthgil noeN
,daeh sih morf werg seldeen dna snip eroM
.reraelc elttil a sgniht ees ot elba flesmih dnuof eh tub
,silopomsoC fo ytic cixot eht ot kcab dekool eH
.egap noertap reh no revo snoertap reh rof etorw ehs seirots trohs ynam dna
.efil wen sih dnif ot kert eht nageb dna
,flesmih gnirutrot saw eh tlef eH
.teef redips naht sevooh ot resolc gnilbmeser ,redrah
.esufer t’ndluow eh tub
.gnileer dnim sih tnes deraeppasid dah ti tcaf ehT
.emils dna dum eht otni knus ydob sih fo tser eht sa llat gnidnats tnorf sih
werg tub ,senips rieht tpek meht fo spit ehT
.hcamots sih sa llew sa aera tsehc eritne sih ,yhcti tlef eH
,tuohs ot detnaw eH
.thguorb ytic eht ssenkrad eht deyojne ohw redips a
.dnuora denrut naitsabeS ,elims degnaf llams a htiW
dekool eh woh pleh t’ndluoc eH
,kcab thgis sih detnaw eH
,sehtolc retniw dennod syawla enoyrevE
!ereht neeb tsuj dah ti erus saw eH ?htrae no tahW
.niap otni nrut ot nageb ssenihcti eht sa
.em rof stiaw ecalp wen A
.pu flesmih peek ot dnuob saw meht fo eno nehw dekcor ylurt reven dah dlrow sih
,egde eht yb tuh a ni devil ohw ekans a saw erehT
”hsipeehS gnileeF“
.drawtuo fo daetsni rellat gniworg dna ecaps gnisol saw taht ytic a ni
,enoyreve devol eH
,deifitnedi eh ,snroH
,reiklis ylthgils saw taht daeh sih no loow eht hguorht fooh rehtona gninnuR
,ecaf sih ta walc ro yawa nur ot gnitnaw tsomla
,werg ti sa delruc dna rekciht ,esraoc werg tI
poleved ot tnaw ot gninnigeb sraet dna gninihw flesmih dnuof eH
.ecalp siht rof ecin oot er’uoY
,rab eht ta sknird mih gniyub
emoh dellac ecno eh ytic eht no kcab sih denrut
,peehs a emoceb dah eH
.mih dellac yeht egdulS ,arboc a saw eH
,gninnigeb wen a saw siht ,oN
.rednow dna tseretni tub ,tsugsid dna raef htiw dellif regnol on noitcerid sih ni secnalg edis
,erom dna erom sih fo ydob wen siht devol eh ho ,denaorg eH
.gnivah rof yoj htiw yrc ot detnaw eh taht elims a dna
.kcab emac thgis sih ,yllanif ,litnU
.osla detegrat eb ton ot eye dnilb a nrut dluow ecilop eht netfo etiuq dna
,mih deppots eciov A
,remocwen eht dlot naitsabeS ”.revir eht oT“
,degnahc mrof sih sa noitanicsaf ni no dehctaw eH ?maerc fo skceps
,naitsabeS rof gnittif saw tI
dellor saw eh ecid eht saw siht ,salA
,deipuccoerp oot neeb d’eH
ynips t’nsaw tI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
!efil wen A !kniht ot ,hO
!ytinutroppo siht etsaw ton dna flesmih tcetorp dluow eh
,mih troppus ot sgel ynam os htiW
sgnidnuorrus sti dna silopomsoC taht gniredisnoc ,gniht egnarts yrev A
,daeh sih fo sedis eht yb ylneddus pord srae yppolf gnileef
dne eht morf spil reh devomer ehs erofeb ,epip eht nihtiw pu gnithgil ruoloc elprup a
.rorret fo spsag eht erongi dna serats eht ffo gurhs dluoc eh syad emos
.silopomsoC ni mron eht erew ecilop toiR
,rat ekil saw dnuorg ehT
,rotinaj a sa dekrow flesmih naitsabeS
,rab s’imoaN ta ylno democlew tlef naitsabeS ,eurt saw hcihW
,gnitatneirosid saw tI !owt tsuj
.tuoba demaerd syawla dah eh efil wen dnarb eht evil ot detnaw uoy fi ot dah eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,ti fo skool eht dah eH
.dluoc eh taht tcatnoc hcum sa gnidiova dna dworc eht fo yaw eht fo tuo gnitteg
.ekoms tuo welb dna
.efil raed rof no gnuh ohw
,thguoht tuohtiw dah eh gnihtolc fo eceip rehto yna dna ffo pot sih werht yldeirruh eH
,daeh sih fo sedis htob nO
,stnap raew d’eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.damon a ekil enola ti ta gniog ro ytic rehtona ot ebyam ,yldliw gnivil
,hsinif ot mih gniggeb
,ti ot desu oot ylpmis erew silopomsoC fo snezitic eht ,revewoH
lladnaR nrob ylwen eht
.tuo gnilggums naht rehtar snaem llew rof ti gnisu eno tsuj saw eh
,sesnes sih dereuqnoc seldeen dna sniP
.edis rehto eht ot uoy ekat ll’I
!retteb eht rof degnahc saw efil sih
.yaw taht dekool ylpmis ti
,ssenippah ni maercs dna lley ot
.mih no dekraps taht lenparhs ynit taht gnirednop
dekan saw eh taht mih ot ecnereffid on edam ti
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,revir eht hguorht miws ot devol ohw stsaeb ylno eht fo eno saw eh
,kcoc desuba llew sih morf detrups etihw fo sgnirts sa seye sih desolc eh ,htuom sih morf bos a dna naorg a htiW
,seye fo riap a ylno hguorht dlrow eht was eh deciton eh ,yrrulB
,ot detnaw eh efil eht gnivil dna yawa gninnur flesmih enigami ot
,mih rehtob t’ndid sreciffo eciloP
,efil hguot a saw tI
.ereht krow thgim uoy
.eb dluow ti wenk naitsabeS sa detullop sa saw revir ehT
,kcalb nar revir ehT
,retawrednu pu dedne t’ndah silopomsoC nosaer ylno eht
.revo ssorc ot tsrif eht t’nsaw eh taht lladnaR ot detacidni snioc fo gnignalc ehT
.ysoc ylbaborp ,arboc a rof tub llams
.ta saw eh ecnatsid eht morf naem dluoc elkniwt taht tahw