.evitamriffa eht ni daeh reh koohs aryK
.ylraelc kniht won dluoc ehs dna
liat dna enam gniwolf dna taoc kcalb ynihs ,dilos eht htiw eram naibarA eht
,denoitseuq tub lootsrab a pu koot annaoJ
sucof ot sthguoht reh depleh niar dna ezeerb thgin looc ehT
”?detnaw I tahw wenk neve I fi…“
.yletaciled os gniwolf enam s’aryK fo skcol eht
.gninnirg ,annaoJ ot esolc nwod daeh reh derewol effarig ehT
”.annaoJ ,oot ma I“ .derepsihw dna
”ecnatsiD eht gnioG“ ,koob sih dna
.thginot egnarts gnitca neeb dah aryK yhw denialpxe ti dna
.aryK ta ylgninoitseuq dekool annaoJ
.reh dessik…dah aryK
.erow ecno ehs taht ecaf deirrow eht decalper elims a erofeb epaga ylthgils gnimoc htuom reh ,gnirats
.hgis a tuo tel dna ,htaerb peed a ni werd ,deb eht ffo deppoh eram yab ehT
”.elttil a xaler dna tuo og dluohs ew ,emag a evah t’nod ew ecnis thguoht maet eht no srehto emoS
,bulc eht deretne dna ,sgnikram rieht tog ,sDI rieht dewohs riap eht ,taht htiW
ffo gnitca saw eram naibarA kcalb ehT
.esiwrehto evah t’ndluow ehs gnihtemos od ot reh ecnivnoc ot gniyrt niaga ecno
sevooh s’aryK fo kcalc ehT ”!tiaW !annaoJ“
,daeh reh derewol annaoJ
.dnim reh otni gnipeerc ylsuolaej fo tib a
.deliaf ehs ,revewoH
”.slrig ,pu smottoB“
.yaw eht gnola tem dah ehs taht lufdnah a htiw desrepsretni
.no emoc ,suoegroG“
.derewsna aryK ”!acinaD ,sknahT“
.taht ekil sserd a ni netfo yrev uoy ees ot teg t’nod I ,sediseB
,kcab dellac annaoJ
”,uoy raeh t’ndluoc I ?tahW“
,moor eht tuohguorht ylfeirb deohce taht noitamalcxe elbidua na htiW
”.uoy erusserp ot tnaw t’ndid ew ,tesolc eht ni erew uoy esuaceb tub
.taoc kcalb dilos a htiw eram naibarA eht
.dneirf tsol-gnol a gniees erew ehs fi sa ylediw gnilims
.siht ta feiler fo tib a tlef annaoJ ”.esnes erom sekam taht ,hO“
,tuo no ereh morf og dluow sgniht woh erus t’nsaw annaoJ
.ecnelis rieht kaerb ot tsrif eht saw aryK
.eye s’annaoJ fo elppa eht yllaer saw eram naibarA eht taht
.egelloc ,won dna ,loohcs hgih ,loohcs edarg emas eht dednetta dah
.aryK rof ylpeed derac ehs wenk ehs tub
.etats evisserped ydaerla s’annaoJ nepeed ot depleh ylno ,wodniw nepo eht no sniatruc eht fo gnippalf eht htiw dexim
.tib a rof dnim reh dnuora taolf sdrow esoht tel annaoJ
.dnah ruoy kram recnuob eht tel tsuj os
.detpurretni aryK
,tniop tsehgih rieht ot dekrep srae reh
.gnortsdaeh dna trevortxe na hcum yrev saw
”…fi wonk ot dah I
.revo acinaD dellac annaoJ
,ekorb yllanif otno gnidloh neeb dah annaoJ taht snoitome fo mad eht
,eerf leef ot detnaw osla dnim reh ,revewoH
,no tnew thgin eht sa cisum esnetni ssel dna ssel ot deremmis staeb bulc gnipmuht ,tsaf eht ,hguone nooS
.nem ot detcartta ylralucitrap t’nsaw annaoJ
.gnol os rof nwonk dah ehs enoemos etad ot lacigol demees ti os
,elbatrofmoc tlef ehs
”,rewsna ym dah I erus ytterp saw
”?thgir ,ma I ohw rof em tpecca ll’yeht
,ereht doots eram naibarA ehT ”.yag m’I .aryK“
”…uoy tuoba draeh ev’I ?ylevol tsuj uoy t’nera ,lleW“
.raef morf deniahcnu
.nalp siht htiw hguorht og dluohs ehs taht annaoJ decnivnoc taht gniht eht
.retnec dna tnorf gnieb ytilauxes nwo reh
a em eviG .thgir er’uoY“
:sevlesruo si ecnereffid eht ,esruoc fo ,ecnecsinimer nI
.maet eht no enoyreve morf pleh dah I tub
yks eht morf tuo dednuos rednuht fo llor wol ehT  foohnorI mok’aT yb
.ydob tcefrep reh tsniaga thgit os tif sserd elprup peed tahT
.noissimda siht yb desirprus ,denoitseuq annaoJ ”?evah uoY“
,denrut annaoJ dna now thgilF
”?em tuoba wonk ehs seod woH“
.enoyna ot deneppah evah dluoc tahT
”?kcils ,evah dluohs I taht ’gnilf‘ siht rof tseggus uoy dluow ohw tsuj dnA“ .detrons annaoJ
.dehcaorppa ehs sa tuo gnar tlahpsa eht no llaf-fooh hcae htiw
”.acinaD ,uoy knahT“
,annaoJ dniheb morf ,nehT
.ti otni reh deklat dah aryK esuaceb aedi eht deniatretne ylno ehS
.sknird erom wef a dna doof rab emos deyojne ,ffo deird tog
.gnicreip erew seye rebma reH
,oga syad fo lufdnah a ylnO
.ti tuoba gnikniht pots t’ndluoc ehs taht os hcum os
”…dna struh daeh ym dna edistuo yraerd os tsuj s’ti dna yug taht tuoba tespu tib a llitS .kcils ,gnihtoN“
”.annaoJ teem ,acinaD .erofeb ereh neeb reven s’ehS“
”.yleerf knird lliw esroh eht ,semitemos ,hguohT
.tuoba enam reh detfihs ezeerb eht sa
reh dnuora esoht ot gnittimda yllautca fo diarfa oot saw ehS
,sthguoht suoutlumut yb dekcarw saw dnim reh ,yadot emit dnoces eht roF
.semag yawa rof moor a gnirahs ro
.gnineve eht ni reilrae dah yeht sknird cilohocla gnorts eht ro
.ynihs dna demoorg-llew os syawla saw taoc kcalb reH
aryK ot timda ot flesreh gnirb t’ndluoc ehs ,esrow hcuM
”!suoiciled ti llac I
.daD regdaB yldduC ,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
.enoyna etad ot uoy nwonk reven ev’I dna reverof sdneirf neeb ev’uoy ecnis
.reporp roolf ecnad eht no erew yeht litnu dworc eht hguorht yaw rieht devaew riap eht
taoc onibaS a htiw esroh gniklaw yab ehT
.dellepmoc ylddo tlef I tub ,dednahrednu saw ti wonk I .haey ,lleW“
”!noitarbelec elttil a rof emit s’ti kniht I
.reppot yllej teews dna edanomel knip eht yb tuo denword ylkciuq saw ti ,ereht saw
.thginot detrops ehs sserd der deniuqes eht erow annaoJ hcihw no noisacco erar eht saw tI
”.noillats laer a sediseb ,lleW
noitaitnereffid tuohtiw si
aedi s’acinaD yllaer saw tI .haeY“
.daeh s’annaoJ otni deppop noitseuq a nehT
,revewoh ,deksa saw ehs
.nwonk reven dah ehs taht modeerf a decneirepxe annaoJ ,tnemom siht nI
”.etaudarg uoy erofeb gnilf eno tsael ta evah ot DEEN uoY
tsehc reh ni gnitaeb traeh nwo s’annaoJ fo mhtyhr eht dehctam tsomla tI
.detad dah ehs ohw nosrep tsrif eht dellik tsomla dah ehs
,dnim s’annaoJ no ylivaeh dehgiew gniht eno ,revewoH
.os enod dah ehs gnizilaer ton ,duol tuo delbmum annaoJ ”…spil esoht dnA“
.cisum…eht tuoba…duol tuo gnikniht tsuj saW .gnihton…mU“
.sgnos dellif noitome tey wols ot gnidael yllautneve
,annaoJ ”?ti si tahW“
”?suoegrog ,gnorw s’tahW .pu dloH !yeH“
.pu denaelc uoy teg s’tel ,no emoC
.yrd ot nageb tsuj dah taht taews eht gnicalper
.tuo pils thguoht taht tel d’ehs taht dessarrabme
,seram dekaos niar fo riap eht dnuora mra na depparw acinaD
rab naibsel a ot reh thguorb dah aryK dezilaer annaoJ taht neht ylno saw tI
,ecnad ot deunitnoc ylpmis riap eht
.gnorw erew gnihton fi sa raeppa ti ekam ot yletarepsed gnitpmetta
.seram eht gnidnuorrus pmal tol gnikrap eht fo olah eht edisni dnats ot revo yaw reh edam acinaD
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.delkcuhc eram naibarA ehT
”.yrros…m’I…I…annaoJ“
.rab eht drawot emit siht
,moor reh ni ereh gnidnats saw aryK
eb dluow yllamron ti naht rehtruf wolg sti esuffid ot depleh ylno niar ehT
saw efil reh fo ytniatrecnu tsetaerg eht ,revewoH
.gniunitnoc ,ylediw delims naibarA ehT
.detapissid yltnatsni
hguohT .annaoJ ot enivid saw knird eht ,yldetcepxenU
.taht fo erac ekat ll’I“
,saera gnignahc ,smoor rekcol eht ni suovren gnimoceb srehto eht ot detfihs syawla cipot ehT
”.dnoces a ni pu eb lliw sknirD .owt uoy ,seirrow oN“
.aryK ot txen gnittis yllaicepse
.etad a no tuo og dluohs riap eht ebyam reh decnivnoc taht aryK fo gniddorp eht hguorht ylno saw ti teY
,timda ot dah eram yab eht ,sseldrageR
.5202 ni emitemos yllufepoh
”.deb ni skaerf laer eht era ohw seno teiuq eht s’ti
…dellems ehs yaw eht ,liat dna enam reH
doom eht tsuj saw ti fi erus rehtien
,niaga ecno decarbme owt eht sA
.ylthgils dedaf ylno ssenisaenu eht ,llitS
”.terces a…tog I…I“
tem tsrif dah yeht ecnis reve rof denip ylterces dah ehs taht
,noitom eno htiw ,neht aryK
.og eno ni ssalg eritne eht denwod
yehT .efil reh fo tsom rof nwonk dah ehs taht ”sdneirf“ eseht fo eno neeb dah ybraD erodoehT ”?oehT tuoba woH“
;yas yeht tahw wonk uoY
.erofeb dah reve ehs naht rethgit reh gnidloh
sa gnioD .pu saw gnihtemos leef ot tub pleh t’ndluoc annaoJ dna
.gnos eht htiw taeb ni llits
.suoegrog ,no emoC“
.niaga ecno daeh reh ni deyalp noitasrevnoc eht sa dehgis annaoJ
.edisni delttob ti peek ton dluoc annaoJ
.thginot tuo og ot detnaw uoy fi ees ot gnikcehc saW !annaoJ ,yeH“
.seulb dna sknip fo wolg a ni tol gnikrap denetsiom eht gnitanimulli
,foohnorI mok’aT yb
.skeehc reh nwod yleerf dewolf sraet eht dna
,drusba ,elitsoh naht
,bulc eht fo srood elbuod eht morf tuo gnir ot nageb esualppa fo dnuor a
,ssik rehtona derahs riap eht nehT
.sdrow s’aryK gniraeh ta niar gnillaf eht ekil annaoJ revo dehsaw feileR
,tuo dellac aryK
”!nwot ni sknird tseb etulosba eht tog ev’yehT“ .demialcxe aryK
.yrenecs fo egnahc a saw dedeen ehs tahw ebyam ,niaga nehT
.luos eltneg dna ,tiw kciuq sih
,annaoJ .lufituaeb os si evol gnuoY“
,acinaD htiw gnieb saw aryK yldneirf woh tsuj niks s’annaoJ rednu teg yllaer ot gnitrats saw tI
’sedanomeL kniP teewS‘ s’acinaD fo eno rehtona gninwod erofeb deggurhs aryK
.sivlep nekorb a htiw tnemom yrev siht ta latipsoh a ni eb t’ndluow erodoehT ebyam
reh revo dleh lohocla eht tceffe revetahw dna
.reh gnikatrevo saw tcnitsni thgilf reh dna
,ecaf reh gniyrd deunitnoc annaoJ
,efil reh fo ytirojam eht nwonk dah ehs taht esoht erew sdneirf tnerruc reh fo tsoM
.llew sa reh rof derac aryK taht tnerappa osla saw tI
,thgil cirtcele sti gninihs ,”selbats-nU ehT“
.snoitamriffa evitisop ta tpmetta reh deyaws sthgilp srehto eht fo tniopretnuoc ehT
.taht yb tnaem ehs tahw tuoba annaoJ ot yretsym a llits hguoht
.etal fo sa emit hguor a gnivah neeb dah
.remrahc eniuqe eht
”.knird a sdeen dneirf yM .owt ti ekam tub ,haeY“
,ruf dna ,enam ,sehtolc reh otni dehsaw niar ydaets ,looc eht
.ruessionnoc a morf raf saw ,erofeb lohocla knard dah ehs hguoht
”?knird eht rof hcum woh ,yeH“
.sselesoprup dna ,drusba ,elitsoh
.erodoehT tuoba yrrow uoy t’nod ,lriG“
”!ecalp siht evol ot gniog yletulosba era uoY
,seram fo riap eht ot ffo sknird owt gnissap
.tuo dnuof maet reccos eht fo tser eht fi
:thgilF ro thgiF“ saw sihT
,erutuf raen eht ni dehsilbup eb lliw
.dnuorg eht ot detoor ylmrif dah annaoJ sevooh eht hguorht tuo deniard raef dna ,gnidih
.sehctolb krad eht dnuora revlis fo skaerts htiw detnemgua neeb dah nrettap taoc reH
.gnorw saw gnihtemos wenk ,annaoJ ta dekool ehs sa noos sa ,aryK
,htrof dna kcab deyaws yeht
,aryK ot denetsil ton ehs daH
”…og annaw I fi wonk t’nod…I“
.puorg a sa tuo og dluow yeht ,sediseB
,detarapes spil s’riap eht sA
,aryK ta derats ehS
,ecaf reh no kool gniwonk a
.gnignol detartsurf fo tsepmet eht kcab dloh ot yletarepsed deirt ehs sa dehca taorht reh dna
.hcum oot tib a evah ebyaM .gniknird ,enola ereh m’I
,moortser eht ot pirt kciuq a sediseB
kconk a ,rehtea eht morf tuo dehcaer enilefil a fi sa ,nehT
.nrub taorht reh tlef annaoJ .delffins annaoJ
,dnuora gnilriwt erofeb ssik ria na annaoJ welb aryK
.sgnileef eurt s’annaoJ wenk aryK ylno fI
,drawrof dessergorp niaga ecno emit fo noisnemid ht4 eht sA
,foohnorI mok’aT yb ”seraM owT fo liaT A
”.dne eht ni mih rof tuo krow lliw gnihtyreve erus m’I
.lootsrab a dettap dna annaoJ ot denrut aryK
.knird reh deppis ,noitatiseh emos htiw ,annaoJ
?eromyna supmac dnuora ecaf reh wohs ehs dluoc woH
.sregnif rieht gnikcolretni
.rood reh morf emac
.lufituaeb saw…aryK
.ylevitarugif dna yllaretil htob
,thguoht I dna esolc demees owt uoy ,lleW“
.ffo aryK tuc annaoJ
.cisum eht htiw nosinu ni gnivom seidob rieht
,rae s’dneirf reh ot txen yltcerid htuom reh gnicalp
.maet reccos etaigelloc s’nemow eht fo srebmem rehto lareves yb yltrohs dewollof
,emit gnol a ni ecno rof dna
,gniyaws reh deppots aryK
”.taht erahs ot deen oN !yeh ,yeH“ .ni depmuj aryK
”…maet eht dna loohcs tuoba gniklat tratS
,elzzum reh ssorca hsulf taeh a tlef ehS
!emit eht lla ereh emoc I“ ,desuap aryK ”,hO“
reh revo hsaw eht niar eht dewolla dna
.sdneirf…emoceb evah I dna acinaD .enola ,semitemoS
.reh gnitpurretni ,deppots tub annaoJ raeh ylerab dluoc aryK
,etats ekil-ecart raen reh fo tuo thguorb ylneddus saw annaoJ .deilper aryK
.’edanomeL kniP teewS‘ a ti sllac acinaD“
.deretne aryK erofeb elbatneserp flesreh ekam ot detpmetta dna
?dezilatipsoh saw eh taht won mih ot gnihtyreve nialpxe
,bulc eht deretneer aryK dna annaoJ
,annaoJ rof hcum oot tsomla saw ti fo llA
,daetsni dnah reh koot tub
”?wonk yeht oD ?setammaet ruo tuoba tahW“
aryK no ecarbme reh desaeler annaoJ
,tnatiseh saw annaoJ hguohT
.roolf ecnad eht no naht yletanoissap erom
”?thginot dnA“ .deilper aryK
,ecarbme s’aryK detacorpicer annaoJ
,kcab daeh reh dellup
,sdneirf ym yllaer er’yeht fI“
.s’annaoJ no ylerauqs spil reh gnitnalp erofeb
.dnim s’annaoJ ni dnuora gnitaolf stbuod ynam llits erew erehT
”!ees on emit gnoL !acinaD yeH“
,annaoJ gard ot deunitnoc aryK ,ylkciuQ
.aera rab eht gnidnuorrus sthgil kcalb eht yb detautnecca saw taht allerbmu llams a dah osla hcaE
.thgir saw aryK ebyaM .noitautis elohw eht tuoba esnet ssel gnileef saw ehs ,metsys reh ni knird a dah ehs taht won
,reh dnuora enoyreve ot deil ehs dah ylno toN
,mih gnisu yb dneirf a derujni dah ehs tub
,annaoJ gnisahc morf htaerb fo tuO
,yks eht drawot elzzum reh detniop
,aryK ot tsnwonkebnU
”.thginot ereh emac uoy taht yppah os m’I
,detcepsus lla eW
.riap eht gnoma eno suoegrog ylurt eht saw aryK
;knird reh dehsinif osla dah annaoJ ,gnol erofeB
.seye reh morf raet a depiw effarig ehT
,erodoehT ecaf ehs dluoC
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,latipsoh eht ni mih tisiv t’ndid uoy gniredisnoC
.denoitseuq annaoJ ”?ssem siht lla htiw devlovni mih teg yhW ?erodoehT tuoba tahW“
,haeY“ ,delkcuhc annaoJ
,tol gnikrap eht ot gnidael srood elbuod eht hguorht dehsarc ehs sA
.ecaf s’aryK nopu dils elims yls A
.aryK rof yletarepsed os denip annaoJ
yojne esaelP  .daD regdaB yldduC
,detcelloc dna mlaC
”!ereh emac ew yhw s’tI !ecnad s’teL
.gniyalp nageb ssab yvaeh htiw gnos a sa ylevil erom emaceb ylneddus roolf ecnad eht no gnorht ehT
.yna uoy pleh t’now ereh dnuora gnittis ,yawynA“
,pu kcab daeh reh desiar acinaD
,ythgilf dna sregnarts fo yraw saw annaoJ ,seniuqe tsom ekiL
,eb thgim taht dnik revetahw ,lohocla eht fo etsat eht
,tnemom a roF ”?kcils ,ti si tahw
.mih ot gnihtyreve nialpxe ot tog tsuJ
.drow reh peek dluow aryK wenk annaoJ
”,srovaf wef a aryK nwo I ,yas tsuj s’teL .esuoh eht nO“
.bulc eht nihtiw morf gnimoc staeb gnipmuht eht delffum ylthgils ylno dna
;ssik eht ’hctac‘ ot ria ytpme eht otni hcaer ot tub pleh t’ndluoc annaoJ
”.smrod eht ot kcab uoy ekat ll’I esimorp I ,ruoh na retfa nuf gnivah t’nia llits uoy fI
,yllacimhtyhr tsomlA
”seraM owT fo liaT A
,sdaeh ’srehto eht fo edis eht ot dleh selzzum ,tsehc ot tsehC
.gnihtyreve kaos ot deunitnoc niar eltneg a sa
.dednetni dah ehs naht retsaf hcum
.yoc elims reh ,annaoJ ot kcab dekool aryK
.won naht emit retteb a eb reven dluow ereht wenk annaoJ
.ssensuovren drawot dehcni dna laivoj ssel ot detfihs noisserpxe s’aryK ”?sdneirF“ ”.sdneirf…emoceb
.rednetrab effarig elamef ,ylevol dna ,llat rehtar a doots ti dniheB
.dediova neeb evah dluoc siht fo lla ,esrow nevE
”?lausu ehT ?neeb uoy ev’woH !aryK“
.flesreh ot thguoht annaoJ
”!sriatsnwod uoy eeS .suoicerP .erA .uoY“
.naibsel a saw ehs
uoY‘ ,gniyas eht wonk uoY“
,tsacdop ’s’ynaffiY tA renniD‘ eht fo tsoh eht s’eH
.elbaresim gnihtyreve edam niar tnatsnoc ehT
.gnihtyna gniyas rehtien
,annaoJ dnuora smra reh werht dna
annaoJ rof deppots dlrow eht ,tnemom a roF
,sevles laer ruo eb ot ytiliba eht tuohtiw
,rab eht drawot dellup gnieb saw annaoJ
,wonk uoY .sdneirf ,haeY“
,niar gnidnenu ylgnimees eht yb dekaos yletelpmoc woN
,yrrow eht lla ,tnatsni na nI
,dnuora flesreh gnuws acinaD
”.ffo daol a ekaT .tiS .no emoC“
,gniylper ,nwo reh otni sdnah s’annaoJ fo htob gnibbarg erofeb
.tuo gnimoc rof delucidir dna dezicartso setelhta rehto nees dah ehS
eb dluow ti drawkwa woh enigami ydaerla dluoc eram yab ehT .taob eht kcor ton dna erew sgniht yaw eht htiw no yrrac tsuj ot tseb ti tlef annaoJ ,hcus sA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,tsiaw s’aryK dnuora morf deppord smra s’annaoJ
,rehtegot gnicnad sruoh eerht txen eht fo trap retteb eht tneps aryK dna annaoJ
!emit elohw siht elgnis neeb dna egelloc ni roinuj a er’uoY
!lriG“ — .taoc kcalb ynihs ,dilos eht htiw eram naibarA eht morf erusaert a
.kcart no kcab flesreh teg ot dedeen ehs tahw yltcaxe saw ereh gnimoC
,eye s’dnim reh ni ,draeh neht annaoJ
,seye reh desolc annaoJ
,rentrap a gnivah yojne thgim ehs taht dediced yllanif dah annaoJ ,22 fo ega gnuoy eht tA
.eram lufituaeb a hcus saw ehS
.oot ,sserd eht tuoba thgir saw aryK ”.thgirla ,lleW“
”?mih tuoba od I dluohs tahW ?oehT tuoba tahw ,oS“
,edistuo morf niar eht fo taeb evissucrep eht
.won eb nac sa raelc
,dnah s’annaoJ debbarg neht ehS
,od ot tuoba saw ehs tahw ta ydob reh hguorht nar taht ssensuovren fo rettuhs a saw ereht hguohT
.suoegrog reh dellac syawla dah aryK
,ronaemed teiuq yllamron sih detaicerppa ehS
:thgilF ro thgiF“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.nepo srood ,ni emoC“
seye s’annaoJ otni ylpeed derats dna
.mih ta kool uoy yaw eht ees I ,lriG“
”.kcils ,ruoh na ,ekil ,ni og ot ydaer eB .tib
,thguartsid yllanoitome ,annaoJ
,sdrow htiw ngis noen tnaig a
”.gnos taerg a s’tI !haeY“
.elims yoc a dna aryK drawot kniw a htiw ,dias acinaD
.pot no gnitaolf diuqil hsiwolley ,raelc a dah taht diuqil knip thgirb htiw dellif sessalg htob
,eram naibarA eht ,aryK ,seniuqe tsom ekilnU
.sreehc suoirav htiw gnola
.dne no doots ydob reh no riah yreve dna
,ylyls dennirg aryK
,sraet htiw tew werg seye reh
.kaep sti ta saw tcnitsni thgilf-ro-thgif s’annaoJ
.derruls ylthgils dna derepsihw erew sdrow reH ”.annaoJ…yeH“
rehto gnihtyna eb dlrow eht nac woh
.loohcs edarg ecnis nwonk dah ehs yug a htiw tuo og ot reh gnicnivnoc aryK dneirf reh
.yrots revoc a dna dnats thgin-eno a neeb evah ot desoppus ylno saw erodoehT ,annaoJ roF
.wonk d’I woh eb dluow siht em dlot gnihtemoS
.dneirf reh tsuj naht erom won saw
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR  ?sselesoprup dna
,liat dna enam gniwolf dna taoc kcalb ynihs ,dilos eht htiw eram naibarA eht ,aryK
”seraM owT fo liaT A :thgilF ro thgiF“
.aryK ecaf ot denrut dna ,seye reh denepo
.detarepsaxe erew sdrow s’aryK
.nwot eht no tuo thgin nuf a tsuJ .erusserp oN
.nosaer a rof éhcilc a eb ot dah noitamrofni gnivah syawla srednetrab fo éhcilc eht ,sediseB
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.pu denaelc dna niar eht fo tuo owt uoy teg s’tel ,seidal ,netsiL“
.rab eht morf yawa reh gnillup
,ereh ydaerla er’ew ,yenoH“
drawrof deppets aryK
,stsiaw s’rehto hcae dnuora depparw smra s’rehto hcae htiw sevlesmeht dnuof seram fo riap ehT
.flesreh dna aryK neewteb noitasrevnoc eht ot kcab tnew dnim s’annaoJ
.’knird reh ekam t’nac uoy tub ,retaw ot esroh a dael nac
,dias ,ssab gnipmuht eht revo gnituohs ylraen ,aryK ”.cisum…eht
”.sdneirf dna ,cisum ,gnicnad fo thgin a ekil etiuq ydegart a tegrof ot uoy spleh gnihtoN
,aryK saw rood eht fo edis rehto eht no eciov ehT
.spmud eht ni saw annaoJ nosaer niam eht t’nsaw taht ,revewoH
.dworc gniniamer eht hguorht dluoc ehs sa tsaf sa bulc eht fo tuo gnitnirps
.gnineve eht yojne ot yrt dna ni gniog htiw hguorht wollof ot hguone tnedifnoc leef annaoJ edam tI
dlrow eht hcihw ni emit a stsap ruo ni evah ew ,netfo oot llA
.bulc eht edisni kcab meht gnidael
.dnim delbuort reh ni gnilriws sthguoht fo mortsleam eht nihtiw srewsna on dnuof
,dnuora daeh reh deppihw effarig ehT
pu tas ylkciuq eram yab ehT
.oga sraey lareves