,detator dna tsif a otni desolc dnah sti tub
.strihs cihparg deniats dna snaej lausac ylbanoihsaf
,sgat s’ralloc reh ot ti hcatta ot gniyrt setunim eerht detsaw ehS
”?yadnoM txen dereviled llifer a deen uoy lliW
.reh detceted eh tnemom eht eelf ot deraperp panS
.woleb seirots ytfif etercnoc eht ot nwod dekool reven eH
,tnemtrapa eht dedoolf tnecs deew hserF
sreganam roines sih ta gurd dezilagel yltnecer eht devaw eh
.ton naht netfo erom yaw nwo rieht ni tog swalc fo stes eerht tub
.tnemtrapa s’ekuL evoba rood eht ot depael dnA .denruT
.srekaens detniap sih dnuora gnivaew ,racrevoh eht otni bruc eht ffo detrad ehS .dewollof panS
,dias ti ”,edur woH“
epip eht gnirolocsid knug kcalb htiw gnob A
— telliks nori tsac dnuop ytnewt a debbarg mra rehtonA
.gat reh tsniaga delttar dna ,no deyats tI
.sgniward moorhsum citsilaer htiw derevoc
.elttob foorpdlihc a tuo dellup dna
.tibbar a ekil racrevoh eht ffo depael ekuL
.retupmoc sih ssecca em pleh uoy dna
.reh dnif ot deganam eh fi neve
.ylleb reh ot pu emoc ev’dluow ti
.sdeen reh ot elbatius emoh a evah ot ylekil namuh a detceles ehs
.morf emac tniap dna deew hserf fo llems eht erehw
.woleb gnilgnad segakcap fo sten deirrac yeht dna
.emit yna em evig t’ndid yeht
,oga htnom a kcab s’latnuK dniheb enog ev’dluohS
,tegdag ynit eht morf emac won eciov siH
.daerht rehtona wollof ot emiT
.epor pmeh htiw dexim tihs laer ekil dellems tihs citehtnys eht tuB
.eciffO sreparcsykS traeH eW
”.noitseuq ym rewsna t’ndid uoY“
.noitcnuf alseT detnetap a
.smoor ruof naht erom deniatnoc ecalp sih detbuod ehs ,yralas hceT giB sih etipseD
”,secafrus no gnipmuj ysiaD ekil t’nseod ekuL .seigolopA“
”rotnevnI tsoL a gnidniF“
,esle gnihtyna llems t’ndluoc ehs ,ekoms deew fo doolf eht htiW
”?eman ruoy evah I naC“
.renroc eht ni toc gnipeels a htiw ned pirt a otni del
.ecived eht ta dettab panS .kcilC
.seirots yrruf dna ,rorroh
,panS dednilb ylraen llab ocsid wobniar gnitator a
,kcab deppilf srae s’panS
,tamrood eht no xob draobdrac a gnicalp no desucof ,enord ehT
”.noitamrofni uoy gnissap yb erefretni yltceridni
.ylreporp reh dettep rotnevni reh litnu kcen s’yorT dettubdaeh panS ,gnirruP ”.racrevoh
,retupmoc sih no tac a gniees fo seiromem sih eveileb reven d’eh os ,dnim sih fo tuo dekab teg d’eh depoh ehS
.emit emas eht ta rotnevni gnissim reh rof kool dluoc ehs
.ruf reh gnirettab dniw ksirb eht saw tnialpmoc ylno reh dna
,sgel rebif nobrac reh derevoc ruf kcalb citehtnyS
”.flesmih tnemtrapa eht otni uoy thguorb yllacinhcet ekuL sa ,noitpmussa elbanosaer a eb dluow tI
”.dlohesuoh eht fo resu deretsiger a ton er’uoY“
.sdnarts tsellat eht deraelc ylerab sredluohs reh
.oga sraey evif taht neeb ev’dluohs ,lleW .eno tsetal ehT“
,teef sih delcric panS
.eson reh ot detfaw stniap cilyrca fo llems tniaf ehT
.sigroc yknohc fo srekcits yb pu dleh
.tsehc reh ot esolc wap cinagro reh dleh ehs
;liat reh dehsal panS
;eciffo sih ni neddih tnioj a flah revo dnim sih tsol evitucexe enO
-- laed a uoy tuc ll’I
,ereht nwod dereknuh ehS
.hctip eht devol rotceriD ehT
,level htruof eht ot nwod dils ehs
.loirtiv s’rehcaerp teerts a dna
.sracrevoh nredom naht erom senord s’yrutnec tsal eht delbmeser taht selcihev ynit desu seirevileD
trihs s’yorT pu delwarc ehS
”?saw eman ruoy yas uoy d’tahw -- laeD“
.dnuorg eht dekcams liat reH .deksa panS
,denway ehS .dias yorT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
drawkcab a htiw kcab ti deggut dna
,tseivaeh s’proCraeP deniatnoc
.klim deripxe dna rehtaelp fo knats tI
,erutsop tcefrep htiw doots ehs fI
,resu deretsiger a uoy ekam t’nac I .eniF“
.roolf nepo eht ssorca deklaw dna
,smra eht fo enO ”.laeD“
.der denrut eye cirtcele eht ,evots eht otno deppord yltneG
.tegdub doof ylretrauq reh semit net ot pu rof dlos soediv fo stros esoht sa
.ffulf eht otni deppord ehs nehw ecnalab reh tsol panS tub
.nihc reh rednu dehctircs yorT sa desolc-flah seye reH
teprac eht ni hsa eht gninioj seceip elttil
,tnemtrapa rieht ni yorT fo ecart a tuohtiW
.ecnahc reh koot ehs
.rood eht nepo dils yllaunam ehs sa delbmuf sregnif reH .dias yorT
”.rennid mraw a em kooc dnA
srotom gnizzub rieht
,gnorw saw ehs fI
,siht ekil srettam ni yltcerid erefretni em tel t’now gnimmargorp yM
.deworran seye neerg s’panS dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,eeffoc fo llems eht ni tsol ylraeN
,gnisu mih dedrocer ev’uoy sdrowssap eht hguorht em klaw nac uoy tub
,roolf yawllah eht sa level emas eht no eb ot deraeppa teprac ehT
,erutinruf eht dnuora ti evrews
snoitaroproc eht fo eno yb deyolpme tegrat a yllaicepse
,gniliec eht morf gnignaH
.daeh reh ot eltsoj a sa hcum os tuohtiw tcapmi eht koot swap citehtsorp reH
.pu ti tes ot derehtob reven ekuL tub ,ecalkcen a rof dengised yekcihood elbatrop a s’erehT ?woh tub ,dluow I“ ”?evael tsuj uoy t’nod yhW .ssorG“
.sgniteem trohoc esnet ni
.dias hguH ”,etunim eno ni evirra ll’yreviled ehT“
— ledom potpal ecnamrofrep tsehgih
.teprac naelc hguorht ti deluah ehs sa
.bmilc eht ot tes dna
.eye reh ot gnihton dedleiy
,emac sretnuhdaeh s’proCraeP nehW“ .dias yorT
.ruf cinagro yssolg reh ot derapmoc neve yklis
,ysae saw tnemtrapa s’ekuL hguorht gnitagivaN
.elprup llud denrut ecaf sih elihw
,evisserpmi gnihton pu denrut tnuh reH
”?lleh eht woh ,panS
.nepo deppop dil s’elttob eht nehw dehgis eH .detnurg eh
.ecruoser laitnesse na emaceb latem taht won elbaulav
.lwob eht otni ti gnikam tsom tub
.ria reh htiw deew delahni ehs nehw dehguoc ehs
,nam a fo eert gnirebmul eht dewollof ylisae panS
.detiaw ehs ,esnet selcsuM
,elbat yggel a dna stenibac ssalg nairotciV
.krowten lanretni s’proCraeP ot ssecca evah ot dah potpal siH
.hcuoc eht rednu dekcud ehs ,ecaps gnivil esraps eht ssorca gnitnirpS
,swalc reh desaeler panS
.revoc elbatius t’nerew
.ffo racrevoh eht dnes ot ecirht nottub eht gnippat
.ydob hpromotce dna thgieh suolucidir sih ot sknaht
,xim eht otni swap raer reh fo eno gnidda deirt d’ehS
,erutxet fo ecnadnuba na htiw elyts tcartsba ni enod ,sgnitniap ruetamA
sterces etaroproc gnirutpaC
reh dna ,sserd a ekil reh revo depard trihs dezisrevo reH
?em dnatsrednu uoy refni t’nac I kniht uoY“
,tekcop sih fo tuo bof a dellup retaewS samtsirhC
.dom eciov eht gnippord
”!noitaroproc eibmoz a ton er’ew ,proCraeP ni ylf t’ndluohs tihs tahT ?rood
.rotnevni reh rof tuocs ot edisni eht no kool a dedeen ehs
.roolf htooms eht ot ti edam gab eht ,yllaniF  .sexob retteb
,sreparcsyks esoht lla gnibmilc retfa nevE
.teef rieht dnuora gnivaew tac eht dnimreveN
litnu ria eht hguorht gnillaf eerf
,kcab kcen reh denarc ehS
.eliforp s’yorT dnuof ehs nehw dellirt panS
.enord eht tiH .depael panS
”?IA emoh lamronba na evah stnemtrapa rehto ynam woh
.derettum ehs ”,reltnE yorT“
s’ekuL .sworc fo redrum a ekil yks eulb eht derevoc seriw eht erehw pu rO
”,tcerroc s’tahT“ ”?ti siht sI“
.redluohs a revo deppolf dna
”.yllaer ,won …ni dnim sih fo tuo denots eb ot gniog s’eh tub ,edis sih sevael reven gniht ehT
?tnemtrapa sseltops a evah mih ekil bols a dluoc esle woH
”rotnevnI tsoL a gnidniF“   yojne esaelP
.loow neerg ylgu s’retaews eht no dekcelf tniap egnaro dna deR .linifadom dna
,ti dellup ehs nehw dedilg ti woN
,retaews samtsirhC neerg noen ylgu s’tluda gnuoy eno ot gnulc riah tac etihW
.tnadnecsed s’ti ro -- eiwoW iuaM sa dnarts eht deifitnedi elppaenip fo ecart tniaf eht
”,dluow ti taht enigami t’nac I“
teknalb eceelf a rednu gnidih
.gnihton yllaretil
”!scitenrebyc decnavda htiw dnuora gniklaw er’uoy ekil ton s’tI
.dias panS ”,gnidliub siht ni eb ll’ehS
.etisbew rohtua ryx no
,kcits BSU a delbmeser taht eluspac keels a tuo dellup ehS
.swap reh ni demriuqs ecived eht rof no-pilc ni-tliub ehT .epacse reh rof
,moor rehtona ni gnilffuhs mih draeh ehS
.sgniw enalpria ekil
,tekcop sih morf bof eht tuo dellup dnah tfel siH
.bruc eht tsniaga mih ediseb gnilttes
yb gnilrihw sracrevoh raeh ot hguone wol
.pu fo daetsni nwod debmilc ehs keew a ni emit tsrif eht roF
,slian sih htiw rewolf deew eht ta dekcip ekuL
.kram a rof dnuorg gnitnuh tnellecxe na edam
.skcos reh htiw doowdrah eht no gniiks yllacitcarp
,kroY weN ni rehto yna naht elacs ot tluciffid erom yna t’nsaw gnisuoh etaroproC
.htaerb sih rednu gnisruc ,sdnoces evif rof ti ta dewalc ekuL
.reh ot kcab sih detneserp eh
s’proCraeP fo eno rof deifilauq eh detacidni rac eht ni noitasrevnoc siH
.reppiz s’kcapkcab eht ni kcuts daw a
syawedis gnikcilf srae ,deppots panS
,noitangidni otni delbraw enot deppilc ehT .dias IA eht
,revo srotisiv sgnirb reven eh dnA
,enituor dekool ssenippols sihT
,grebremmoS aniltaK yb
-- emoh tegrat a wollof dna ereht nwod teg ot dedeen ehS
,moordeb reh fo tuo dereteet yorT ,sdnoces nI
.dnuora citsalp fo sbut devom eh sa yltnerehocni delbmurg eH
,gnihton tuoba deirrow I“
,roolf rehtaelp eht ot kcapkcab sih werht ,ni deppets eH
,yawllah eht nwod ti gard ot deganam ylisae panS dna
.nihc reh rednu dehctarcs yorT nehw
,yawrood nepo eht hguorht dessap eH
,ereh noitiutni reh dewollof dah ehS
.reh demraw enola msimitpo
.savnac sih revo derevoh ekuL
.raey tsal elbaliava edam snoitulos citehtnys repaehc ot sknaht ,deew ekil gnihtyna llems t’ndid sbat ylno DBC
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.esolc a ot dils rood ehT
,wodniw tcerroc eht ot tog ehs nehW
.deew elats fo knats
,nosaer a tuohtiw pu hgih siht bmilc t’ndluow parcS
,ycavirp rof kcalb detnit ,swodniw ehT
,esacrewol lla ,si drowssap siH“
eht tuo pihs ot syad orez htiw delddir tcudorp a tnaw uoy oD !snorom uoy ,olleh ,ekiL
”,gninraw eht rof sknahT“
”.pu gnihtyreve naelc ot setunim eerhT
.racrevoh a ni em teg ot setunim owt naht ssel meht kooT
.mih was ehs tnemom eht ecap reh denekciuq panS dna
.ecived eht otni daolpu ot
.sdnah dehctertstuo eht derongi panS
.worromot ti ekaM“
,saw ehs sa dehcuorC
.ni edih ot hguone yleraB
”?ni krow ekuL seod eciffo tahW“
.toc eht dniheb dettauqs tI
,erutinruf rehto eht tuB
desolc-flah seye reH
,sgat atadatem etairporppa eht htiw gniteem devresbo eht detatonna panS
,deppiznu ydaerla ,tnemtrapmoc ehT
detelped yrettaB
,lwob eht ni deew denekcalb eht morf pu delriws ylizal ekomS
,esolc dednuos eH .dellac ekuL
.sgel yggiwt s’elbat eht dna
.smargolik derdnuh eerht revo llew gnihgiew sexob fo eldnub a deirrac eno sihT
”.diarfa m’I ,stellep doof draH“
.rehtegot sregnif rieht dekcilc smra nehctik ehT .dias hguH
.ti demrifnoc erutcip eliforp ehT
.dias eciov deidobmesid a ”,dootsrednU“
”,emoh gniog er’eW“
,dlrow eht ni esle erehwyna naht sreparcsyks erom detsaob
.lluks reh tsniaga dennip
.ecafrus yreppils eht no eussi na tuohtiw no deunitnoc swap cinagroni eerht reH
.yorT dnif d’ehs ecnahc citsimitpo eht no delbmag ehs ,lausu ekiL
,hceT giB fo doolf ehT
nac I esruoc fo tub
.rulb a ruf etihw eht
.dias eciov IA s’rac eht
.potpal eht pu deprub
dnah eno htiw ecaf reh fo tuo riah der fo ssem citoahc reh tpews ehS
,tnirps a ta ffo gnikaT
”,desserts mees uoY“
.depmuj dna ,gnahrevo s’retnuoc eht ot pu dekool
.ytnelp reh evag tac-grobyc sselemoh a gnieb tub
.ssalg eht dekcams dna delwoy panS
”,em esirprus — rennid em ekaM“
?dnuora em sredro eh yaw eht raeh uoy diD
,troper tsal ym etouq oT
,em ot sklat tsuj reven eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.kcab delbmurg panS
,ti hcuot t’nac uoy oS“
.asudeM sa elbazingocer ylerab tsub elbram a saw ,elbat tauqs a no
.kcapkcab dessot eht ot knuls ehS
.ssenidit fo scisab eht nrael reve ot tliops oot dlihc a ekil gnitca nam nworg a fo erutcip eht
”,tuo teg ot nalp a tog ev’I“
.tacesuoh yranidro yna ekil dekool panS
— ssalg gnihceercs eht deciton enon
snamuh eht dehctaw tnalpmi raluco reh ,revewoH
,pu dna nepo deleviws rood tseraen ehT
.swodniw eht ffo eralg eht yb ,niaga dednilb yliratnemom ,detniuqs ehS
,srehto eht lla ekil ,tnemtrapa sihT
.dias eciov deidobmesid eht
,nepo deppop egdirf ehT  .rrup mraw a
”.kooc ot sruoh ekat t’nseod taht rennid a esoohc ot hguone trams eb dluohs uoy nehT“
.pmubtsif a htiw panS gnitneserp
,cinagro eno dna leets eerht ,swap tac elttiL
dedeen d’hguH sa gnol sa eciwt
,srae rieht revo senohpdaeh gnilecnac-esion tsetal eht dna srotinom rieht ot deulg seyE
.llaw eht fo edis rehto eht no stekcar fo not a edam dlihcnam nmad eht dna
sksed rieht revo dehcnuh
,resolc dettort ehs sA
,yawrood eht ta desuap panS
.swap sselbmuht s’panS htiw neve
.gninnur detrats ehs ,tam gnidnal eht dehcuot wap eno tnemom ehT .ffo depmuj panS
ni desserd slanoisseforp gnuoy htiw deggolc steerts eht ,retal setunim owT
stnalp fo ssem reh hguorht deklaw dna
”?ihsus em ekam uoy tuoba woh
.yrevals egaw etaroproc fo dlof eht otni
,grebremmoS aniltaK yb ”rotnevnI tsoL a gnidniF“ saw sihT
.sdrahs ssalg gnirettilg ni derevoc klawedis eht otno depmuj neht
,yltnatropmi tsoM
.nehctik eht fo elddim eht ni dnalsi na dniheb nwod ti polp dna
,ot kcits ot namuh rehtona dnif dna tuo kcab ot etal oot
.edis eht ffo deppils wap cinagro reh dna ,srehto eht erofeb riah a nwod dehcuot swap tnorf reH
”.laem tneced a tac a gnideef droffa nac eh ylniatrec
.meht dnuora ytilaer kaelb eht deciton ylerab yeht
.ecalp ralimis a ni tsub ruatonim a deyalpsid ylduorp yorT ,tnemtrapa suoiverp rieht ni
-- dom eciov a gnisu t’nsaw ti tub
nattahnaM rewoL fo tcirtsiD laicnaniF ehT
.dnuorg gnitnuh hcir a panS dereffo yeht dna
,em htiw uoy ekat ll’I
.senob fo eldnub a debbarg
.gnisuoh etaroproc eb ot dah tnemtrapa sihT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ssalg eht otni gud swalc latem fo stes eerht reH
.mih ot txen dnats a no tas
liat reh dehsal panS
***  ”!panS ,pihsrentrap laicifeneb yllautum siht ot drawrof gnikool ma I
.kcapkcab eht naht eganam ot reisae devorp potpal ehT
,noitcif ecneics setirw ohw
.wonk uoy ,epytotorp tsetrams eht llits m’I
.dezingocer panS dom eciov on ,tsael ta
.ecnayonna eht etarelot dluoc panS tub ,dellihc dniw ehT
,wodniw eht hguorht dlofnu siht lla dehctaw ehs sA
,llet t’naC“ .deksa panS
.delbmum ehs ”,ysae t’nsaW“
,swap etihw yffulf fo tuo gnikop swalc latem gnimaelg eht sediseB
;pu detloj racrevoh eht nehw taes a rednu deppils panS
dnalsi s’nehctik eht dnuora devaew ehs
,tsehc nedoow egral a revo tneb ekuL
.ciffart hcum oot
.dom eciov yrtlus a ni deksa eciov deidobmesid a
.ytiC kroY weN ni gnidliub tsellat eht fo swodniw eht dehctarcs
”.thginot gnivael er’ew -- snalp fo egnahC“
”.slamina ekil leef yeht
.kcapkcab sih fo mottob eht ta stpiecer dna slicnep nekorb eht htiw gniyl ylbaborp s’tI
;ycarucca htiw elggurts ton ot semit hguone siht enod d’ehS
”?resu a em ekam uoy naC“
,tniap citamorhc dna elbac ynihs lla
,renroc rehtona ni gnitniap detrats dna pu doots eh nehW
.selkna eht ta dehcnub stnaptaews niht
rehto hcae ta gnilley dna riah nwo rieht tuo gnillup
,yltnatropmi erom ;ylemosdnah diap
.ni degrab yeht retfa gnihtyna hcuot em tel t’ndluow yeht -- egassem a evael ot emit evah t’ndid I
.ekuL ,taht raeh ot yrros m’I“
nehT“ .tniop eht gnivorp
.ecaps nehctik dna egnuol denibmoc eht sediseb ,smoor rehto owt dah ylno ti ecnis
,hguH“ .dloc eb dluow thgin eht
.senord etaroproc eht devresbo panS
”.noitasrevnoc gninrom a s’taht tuB“ .deb ot kcab
.srae s’panS truh ytilauq rekaeps roop eht dna
”.pu swodniw owt dna tfel eht ot swodniw neetfif tuoba si tsesolc ehT
.reh dnuora yks eht dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,nosinu ni dehctiwt smra citobor suoirav ehT
,ezilibats ot gnireteeT
,teprac etihw enitsirp esiwrehto eht fo tuo sknuhc gnippir ,roolf eht otni knus swalc latem reH .tiag gnilddaw
.rotnevni reh deraeppasid ev’thgim taht
,hcton a pu dekcit eguag erutarepmet s’potevots ehT
?sey ,srentrap su sekam siht eveileb I“
.etad esaeler kcab dehsup eht rof em gnimalb s’maet eht no enoyreve won
eeffoc dellems ehs
,efil ot dehctiwt nehctik eht ni smra citobor yggiwt ehT
.tsrif-ttub dednecsed ehs
hcuoc eht rednu morf delwarc panS
.yawrood eht hctaw ot retupmoc eht morf pu dekool ehs ,gnihsal liaT
.senildaed elbisivni yb nevird
.knis eht ni taes ytfol a morf panS ot nwod deddon tac etihw a erehw
,gnilbmur ylleb dna
,redluohs eno revo gnuls ,kcapkcab siH
,edih ot erehwon htiw sehcaorkcoc ekil delttucs yehT
,dekrow t’ndah ecnallievrus ecniS
.reh ta kcab derats ezag desserpminu reh
grebremmoS aniltaK yb
?em tuoba woh ,lleW“
,ni deggol ehs retfa litnu t’nsaw ti
.decafrus yorT ot detcennoc gnihton tub
,yawrood eht ot kcab pets ot reh koot ti spets ytnewt eht nI
,moor eht fo elddim eht nI
.sllaw eht derevoc
,egap s’yorT rednu detsiL
,dehsal liat deppit etihw reH
.noitcelfer yltsohg reh tsniaga thgirb denihs
”.no tuo vrep ot dom ekaFpeeD a s’ti sselnu
!etakspaehc a tahW“
eht ni dekrow ehs detats noitacol krow reh
,ciffart ria fo wolf eht morf nwod detfird racrevoh enO
.smra dehctertstuo s’yorT otni nwod depmuj panS
.kcapkcab sih deen ll’uoy ,woN
.opyt a edam ehs taht rab hcraes eht dnuof dna
.renroc eht denrut liatynop gnol s’ekuL fo tsal eht litnu ,dih ehS
,nepo ediw ,rood txen ehT
.sllaw owt ro eno dniheb ebyam
.roolf eht no srebme gniredloms eht tuo koohs dna pu ti dekcip ekuL litnu
,ylisae denepo ecived ehT
savnac eht fo tnorf ni deyats eh taht tsurt ylno dluoc ehS
,leseid-nroc dna ,deew
,liatynop gnol a ni kcab sih nwod dedacsac riah dnolb gnol siH
.riah sih gnisruc
,senildaed rieht teem ot delbmarcs snretnI
,tnalpmi raluco eht htiw decalper eno eht ,seye reh fo enO
.rac eht morf eciov yrtlus eht ekil yltcaxe dednuos tI
.esu ot elba eb thgim ehs gnihtemos dah renialpmoc eht tsael ta tub
.racrevoh sih nommus ot yldetaeper ti gnikcilc
”?ecnivnoc I dluow ohw os
.sIA emoh gninnur ton stnemtrapa s’ereht kniht I“
,ruoh rep elim flah ylerusiel a ta seirots derdnuh a nwod gnidilS
.niaga gniklaw detrats ehS .ti derongi panS
,egatnav siht morF
”.sbmil ym hcterts ‌I erom eht ,detacilpmoc erom ehT .gnikooc ekil I“
.tnemtnioppasid ylno
,etalp rennid a naht rediw egdims a smroftalp naht erom elttil erew meht fo spot ehT
!panS“  .rehto eht htiw eye na fo tuo peels eht debbur dna
,roolf eht deffucs srekaens
”?noitanitsed rehtona ot ro emoh gniog eb ew lliW
.tipmra reh ni dezzub ecived gnilevart siH .dias hguH
.top eht otni deppord enob dna ,retaw ,tlaS
.ffuh a htiw roolf eht no deppord ehs
,oga shtnom eerht deraeppasid dah rotnevni reH
.ettelap nedoow a no stniap cilyrca sih pu gnittes emit teews sih gnikat ekuL was ehs
”!gninoitcnuf neeb ev’I ecnis drowssap yreve gniretne mih dedrocer ev’I“ ”.taht
.yawyna ni detrad ehs tub
.ecived s’hguH rof dnuora gnigammur
,eeyolpme proCraeP a s’eH
,sessalg gniremmihs rieht hguorht ytilaer lautriv no dekcol noitnetta rieht htiW
.s’ekuL htiw smra gnikooc citobor dna sroolf doowdrah eht derahs
,htaerb rof gniffuH
,selkcunk sih deppat panS  ”?ti taht si
.sdnah sih fo hself elap eht derucsbo yleritne tsomla dna norpa sih nwod delbbird tniap hserF
,ecaf s’ekuL nees t’ndah llits ehS
.efil rieht gninnur meht naht retrams IA na ekil t’nod spuorg sucof tuB
,moorhtab eht ot del rood tsrif ehT
.wap eno htiw draobyek eht ta dekcep panS ”.eno ycnaf a s’eH .ggb00b205i
mra citobor rehtona retfa tuhs panS ot demit yltcefrep
seirtsepat ciledehcysp dna teprac gahs nworgrevo ehT
?ekuL ,krow saw woH“
,ekahsdnah a rof erutseg a ni tsrif deyalps sregnif stI .nwod dehcaer
.ytic eht ni hcrep tseb eht llits saw siht
,retspmud a fo pot eht no dednal ehs
.swap ruof lla ot deppolf panS dna
”?uoy era tnatsissa esuoh fo dnik tahW“
?panS er’uoy ,gateman ruoy yB !hguH“
.trop a fo daetsni tuo dettuj psalc retsbol a tub
.seciffo nepo dedworcrevo ni
?sdrowssap sih wonk uoy gnimussa m’I“
.tac odexut eht enola tel
.tam gnidnal eht gniraelc
ssalg eht ni delriws egnaro dna kniP
”,eciffO sreparcsykS traeH eW ehT“
.dewols top eht gnirrits mra eht dna
noitcif trohs dehsilbup ryx ot sknil dnif nac uoY
”.doof edulcni segelivirp s’ysiaD gnimussa m’I“
.eeffoc sih deppis eh sa topsdnilb sih ni gniyats
,rae eht dniheb panS dehctarcs
”?eno edur eht s’ohw nehT“ ”.oN“
.yawyrtne eht fo tnorf ni denoitisop yltcefrep saw
,sllaw eht derevoc seivom rorroh rof sretsoP
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
si yrots s’yadoT dna
*** ”.gninrom txen ffo seog mrala ym litnu hcuoc ym morf gnivom ton m’I
.llew sa ereht detsil s’ehs
.dellems ti naht esrow detsat ylbaborp ti
.uoy ot segelivirp s’ysiaD ylppa nac I tub
.taht ekil ksir a gnikat m’I fi ,ysae eb retteb tI
hteet reh ni kcapkcab eht debbarg panS
.melborp eht s’taht ssecca lacisyhp eht s’tI“
,tcefreP“ .dias hguH
--- hguoc dna plug mih draeh ehs tub
.tnemtrapmoc deppiznu eno fo tuo dekaep ti
,ssalg eht otni senil thgiarts-relur gnihctarcs ,tuo swalC
.seulc rof ytic eht deruocs dah panS
,kcapkcab eht edisni daeh reh dekcud ehS
.uoy rof ekuL s’tahT“
.stnalp evissam fo ssem yelttom a ni derevoc saw eno siht tuB
.doowdrah htooms dna teprac neewteb pmuh eht revo kcapkcab sih gard ot derobal ehs sa mih gnihctaw
,nepo dils rood ssalg ehT
seeyolpme hceTniF dna ,amrahP
;eno siht edam ev’tsum retsis redlo s’yorT wenk panS
.roolf doowdrah krad s’tnemtrapa sih no skram kcalb gnivael
,etisbew eeyolpme proCraeP lanretni eht ot desiurc
.deew sih deredro tsuj ekuL“
”,ediw skcolb net revo sdnetxe gnidliub siht woh htiw ,yhw ees nac uoY