.thgin naisiraP ytsorf eht otni
.srallec dekcots-llew dna shtraeh mraw fo segdol taerg htiw yhtlaew saw
,degreme tsetnoc a
snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT morf elbaliava
.raey txen eht reh rof gnitiaw potfoor eht no saw taog ehT
.gnidne-reven eb ot denitsed saw
,reliart eht stops rehsaD
.sevolg raew tsael tA“
.sgol fo gnilkcarc eht tub dnuos on saw ereht tnemom a roF
.flowerew eht morf aococ fo puc rehtona detpecca regdab eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
tuo saw I .eromyna ereht t’nsaw I tub
,meht tsniaga gniggard
ti‘ ,naht yas ot retteb gnihtemos fo kniht ot gniyrt ,nihc sih dehctarcs deraJ ”,lleW“
.reh fo gnikniht saw ehs wonk ysiaD tel dna
ksab ot ,senohpdaeh ym ro
;doohdlihc ecnis sdneirf neeb d’yeht tuB
.trid tfos dna ,ssarg neerg ,yah ytsum fo amora eht gnihctac
,erehwemos teg ot yaw eno tog ylno uoy nehw tuB“
dehsinav tnemtnetnoc s’adnariM
”.dlrow ediw eht otni dna ecnef eht revo ,yllautnevE
.reh morf denrut ecaf kcalb ehT
.eludehcs gniwolfrevo rieht ot dedda pots wen a
.ecalp fo tuo tlef stnemetats dnuoforp
,ffo saw mia s’qcaJ ”!niatuP“
”?boj eht no gnipeelS“
.mih hcaer ot sharonem revlis gnilrets fo yalpsid a hguorht dehsams regit eht sa taobwohs ot ton detcele qcaJ
,yks thgin eht ni semalf deroloc-ynam eht ees dluow
.yrruh ot stnaw ehS
,emit gnol a rof sdneirf neeb ev’eW“ ,dias ysiaD
”.sdneirf wen ekam
”!og ot sah llits tsoh ruO“
”,wonk d’I n’erom s’tahT“
”.won trats ot gniog m’I
”.evaew ot woh nrael ot detnaw syawla ev’I ?thgir ,em nioj ll’uoY .htnom
.yttap egasuas dna ,sgge delbmarcs ,sekacnap fo etalp a htiw deipucco erew setunim evif txen s’flow ehT
.raey eht fo tser eht rof rehsaD tnuah dluow taht eciov a ni kcab dellac ehs
.sgol fo gnilkcarc eht saw moor eht ni dnuos ylno eht tnemom a roF ”.dluoc I fi neve
,elzzum sih tsniaga dedolpxe llab lufroloc eht sa knilc suodnemert a saw erehT ”!haG“ .retsloh sih morf lotsip citamotuaimes a gniward xnyl a ta llabtsaf a ekil ti delruh dna
.ezam eht edisni peed erew eh hguoht sa mees ot eciov sih gniworht ,dellac qcaJ
.swap gnilbmert htiw draobpuc eht ni pucaet tsal eht tes adnariM
nalC mussopO eht tuB
.yawa syad wef a llits saw ecitsloS
,kaeps ton dluow srehto ehT
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT
,foor reliart eht pota noisicerp htiw dednaL
– nac ehs sa noos sa
,revir eht dessorc tsoh dloc eht dna
,flehs eht ffo stnemanro ssalg nwolb fo egakcap draobdrac a gnihctanS
”.tae ot toh gnihtemos ebyam ,tsael ta eeffoc a uoy gnitteg m’I
.tnemom gnol a rof devom anilevaj eht ron ,eltsimocac eht rehtieN
…naretev eht ,noillats eht ,flowsedart ehT
.meht desselb dah ohw emas eht yb yas emos
?gnikam uoy era tahW .raey fo emit siht erif no si ecivres latsop ehT“
”!stoidi uoy ,mih teG“
,gnineve eht yb nosmirc ot norffas morf edahs yreve deniats saw wons nellaf ehT
”.raey wen taerg a ot s’ereH !ecitsloS yppaH“
,noinapmoc ediserif eht deggurhs ”,lleW“
,emac yad eht nehw ,sselehtenoN“
”snosniktA ta gnippohS samtsirhC“ dnA
.yranidroartxe os ton spahrep si taht tuB
.elihw a ni ecno tsael ta suominanu eb ot ecnahc a sevresed gnihtyreve ,lla retfa ,hcihW
.floWcaM boR dna
.tlep kcalb-tej a gnilaever ,flesreh koohs taog eht
,gnihsinav nageb seciov
*** .eciov s’taog eht htiw riap ot egami na
”.thgif ot tub eciohc on dah yeht oS
.etirw ot tahw ediced ot gniyrt setunim fo elpuoc a tneps dna ,pmats a dna drac eht thguob ehS .delims adnariM
.delims dna dexaler adnariM
wohs ot delims adnariM ”.sdneirf dlo ruoy tegrof t’noD“
sthgil yriaf gnilkniwt tsap delbmarcs eh sa
.sdog eht yb desruc neeb osla dah yeht tuB
”.lla retfa tsetnoc eht otni tup ot gnihtemos dah uoy ekil skool“
.daoler ot deppots snoog eht sa esuap desselb a saw erehT
”.dekaos teg lliw swap ruoY
,derehtag srelletyrots demannu tub railimaf-tsomla fo pihswollef suoiretsym a ,emit tsaL
”.seert eht lla ni roloc yreve fo sthgil gnah dluow yeht
,lesnit munimula ni depparw
.gnilwarps mih tnes dna
,niar ekil dellems yletinifed tI
!selas eht yojne ot dnuora eb t’now uoy taht emahs a s’tI“
.yrots nwo ruoy fo uoy gnibbor eb d’taht …sgniht
ecnelis yloh fo dnik euqinu nwo sti setaname taht dnik eht—
.yrt neve ot dessarrabme oot saw ehS
.sdrazah htiw delddir neeb dah spots rieht dna
’?woH ?tahw ,tiaW‘
.srettef reh fo eerf pils lliw ehs
.dnalrednoW s’lëoN erèP gnidniw eht drawot detaerter eh sa
ereh ,llet draeh ev’I os ro
”…seog tsetnoc
.detnetnoc saw ehs
.degnahcxe erew seirots eht ecno
.ereht tuo dloc deedni
”?on ,part gnicnivnoc A“
.keehc reh no egdums a gnidulcni ,erehwyreve ruolf teg ot deganam
,mrywkooB irikeneN ,iluaP secnarF
.modeerf fo reh ot gnis ssenrah hcae gnola slleb ehT
snoihsaf tsetal eht desimorp taht salohciN .tS oced tra eht denimaxe eh
,kcitsdray a sa gnol sa enac ydnac a gnibbarG
.rehtegot meht deit taht senil eht hguorht detarbiv tI
ti hguoht neve ,oot tnew adnariM os gnirehtag egalliv eht ot gniog dekil ysiaD
”!thginot wons ot desoppus s’tI“
.sseccus erutuf yna naht retteb saw tI
.retnuoc yrlewej eht dniheb flesmih delruh qcaJ ,ytinutroppo eht gnizieS
.no tup ot elihw a ekat sgniht eseht“
dedne llits taht yrots teewsrettib tsom eht thguorb dah ohw ees ot
thgiew a ,ecnatsiser fo tnemom a si erehT
renroc eht ni yllufreehc dewolg taht ecniS
.mih dniheb tuhs rood ehT .devaw
.sredluohs gnipols gnol dna ,hself reh hguorht ekop ot demees taht spih
”?spahrep ,gnippohs thgin-etal fo tib a ot pU“
.esirnus ecitslos eht ekil reehc doog gnirettacs ,nehctik eht dnuora demaor ysiaD
.tibbar eht dnuora gniwolg nretnal elbisivni na sa denigami adnariM hcihw ,reh htiw tnemeticxe fo ria na thguorb ysiaD ,syawla sA .moor eht otni dednuob ysiaD sa tsuj evots eht no ti tes dna elttekaet eht dellif ehS ”!nehctik eht nI“
.kcab saw ehs ,raey txen ehT
,dereetnulov tacyella citenrebyc eht ”,og ll’I“
nun enirevlow eht ekil yltcaxe dellems
.emit tsal eht rof
,flow eht dehsinif ”,yas yeht dnA“
,eert eht deggulpnu eH
”,maerd ecin a s’tI“
.snalc eerht devil htap rieht ni yellav eno nI“ ”.dewollof retniw
fo tuo uoy gnikaT .ko s’taht tub
.syebo hgiels eht neht dna
.si tI ”.emit tuoba s’tI“
,sknird erom erew ereht oS
.redic sih dehsinif eh sa dereviuq eannetna yffulf siH
.tekcaj sih edisni repeed tfig eht deppils yllausac qcaJ sa
.sehsid eht gniod no detsisni ysiaD ,ekac dna aet fo lluf erew yeht ecnO
”.si ti tluciffid woh ecnereffid hcum ekam t’nseod
,tlep reh sefahc ti dna ,esool si ssenrah reH
,ahsiM rof tfig tcefrep eht rof tnuh eht taht demees tI
,dehsinif regdab eht ”,sseug I“
,wons fo ffup a timda ot nepo gnuws rood eht neht tuB
.retnuoc yrlewej eht revo tpael
.flesym ,taht ni rettib hcum ees t’ndid I“
,iluaP secnarF yb ”yawA hsaD“
,uoy saw tahT
”.ti tuoba dab leef t’ndluohs uoY“
.esruocsid lacitirc emos rof
,gnol oot nekat sah ehs taht ,enog sah taog eht diarfa si ehS
,sgniht wen fo stol od
.tekcaj dedooh gnittif-lli na ni flow gnikool-derit a
,raey txen eht rof yromem taht peek dluow ehS
.detrons xof desserd-llew eht
”!niagrab a rof erised ym fo em esubasid ton lliw uoY“
.tsetnoc eht htiw od ot gnihtyna ton s’ti“
.kcitseldnac ytfeh a htiw talf mih dekconk
”.yawa nettog d’I thguoht I
.dias ti ”?ekila kool t’nod ew fi tahw oS“
,akrap a ni anilevaj a emac dniheB
.reh rof tiaw ton did taog eht seirrow ehs tub
”.morf emac tsrif siht ekil sthgil erehw s'tahT“
…hguoht ,em ,seirrow tsuj tI
reh edam reehc doog dna ygrene reh tub ,srae trohs rehtar dna ruf nworb nialp htiw ,ta kool ot yranidro saw ysiaD
,hguone ekil mees t’ndid drac A
”.sdneirf tsuj naht erom eb dluohs ew kniht I“
”.gnikihhctih neeb ev’dluohs ydobon ecalpemos ,gnikihhctih ,flow A“
.tnedifnoc syawla saw ysiaD tuB
”!raelc ot rab hgih a s’tI“
,lleW“ .yltnelis deddon adnariM ”?thgir
delffum noitartsurf reh ,wons eht otni spmats ehS .evres ot yppah
”?flesym esucer I yas ew tuobawoH .stsetnoc rof rO
deldnik d’eh erif eht otni yllufthguoht derats god ehT
.laer era ,gnibmulp dna sllib dna sthgilpots ekil naht ,ygrene dna
dluow I .dog a saw eh dias srehtO
.lla ti fo noitcefrep tfos eht yb
,ekac fo tnecs gniregnil eht revO
taoc hcnert savnac derehtaew a ni yaj eulb gnikool-dehsiugnitsid A
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
.reh dniheb dekcor hgiels ehT
,gnicnarp fo tuob trohs a retfa ni delttes maet reH
,meht no ton erew seye s’eno tnemom eht
.tils gnieb taorht reh fo egami na derujnoc taht
nilevaj cipmylO na ekil drows eht delruh qcaJ ,egnar ni ecnO
”!nuf eht lla evah uoy tel t’ndluoc I“
,nehctik eht ot sehsid ytrid koot
.taog eht fo lluf neeb dah smaerd reh ,yletaL
.htaerb reh dleh rehsaD
,ti tuoba seirots gnillet yb esrevinu eht fo trap a gnieb pots t’nod eW
,saw ti revehcihW
.esuoh eht ot dleif eht ot nrab eht morF“ .dias taog eht
.ffo sevolg eht deggut dna retaw eht ffo denrut ehS
.rebma citlaB htiw dialni
eldnah derettaps-doolb eht dnuora wap sih parw ot deganam namhcneh eht
gnihtemos yas ot detnaw ehS
,erusnu demees regdab naretev ehT ”?ton ylbaborP
.detaelb dna dehcnilf taog eht tub ,tlusni na sa ti tnaem t’ndah ehS
,tpael ehs erofeB
!raey ruo eb ot gniog si sihT ?eeS“
).ngis eht no lla saw taht ,sey(
.retniw eht otni tuo ekirts tseug tsal sih dehctaw dna
,hsinav dluow srelletyrots eht ,esruoc fo ,yllausU
,enoyna ot taht od t’ndluow I dnA
.retlehs ekat ot hguone yhtlaew ron
”!ediputs ,ereh revO“
,seirutnec gnol rof redael eht neeb sah ehS
.revlover sih llifer ot
.dael reh swollof maet ehT
.wonk uoy ,raey tsal enog evah dluow I“ .dias taog eht
.delgnij slleb ehT .nepo ti dellup
.noisacco laiceps a saw siht tuB
”!tcefrep oot saw tnemesitrevda siht nwonk evah dluohs I !ehcaVaL ssetnuoC“
,nalC raeB eht ,rehtonA
”,elttil a tuo gnikaerf rof yrroS“
.dlot era seirots erehw
.evoba dnuorg eht no derettap niar elihw moordeb s’worrub reh ni guns gnileef devol ,sthgin yniar devol ehS
’!rehtaew siht ni raf teg t’now uoY‘ ro
.reh delcricne taht secnef eht lla rof ,gniht dliw a ekiL
.ylluferac ,noinapmoc ediserif eht deksa
.dlot er’uoy erehw og uoy dna“
,sthgil erew ecnatsid eht ni woleb dna
”?yrots a tpecca uoy dluow“
.swodahs eht otni dednelb eh sa
.yppas oot erew seno suoires eht dna ,ynnuf yllautca t’nerew sdrac ynnuf ehT
.foor eht fo pil yrev eht ot decnad taog ehT
denrut sah dlrow ehT
”.siht eveileb annog reve ydobon
.mih drawot drawrof denael srelletyrots eht llA
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
.noitseuq eht fo tuo neeb evah dluohs gniyrruh nehw yrruh oT
,rood eht dehcaer d’eh
.noitisop reh fo seirolg eht lla fo tsil a
rekohc reh no sdnarts ybur lacitrev eht dehctam sserd nosmirc reH
”rafA esrevarT eW“
t’noD“ ”!hguorht thgir ,teewsrettib SAW tsuj taht tub ,teews dedda
.wolpwons laer a tog neve s’ytnuoc eht kniht t’noD“
,pots ot sselrewop demees regdab ehT
er’uoy fi tuB .dlot era seirots eht erehw ,ereh
revoc tnadnuba htiw mih dedivorp stfird wons laicifitrA
.eerf redloh ragic eht gnihctans erofeb retnuoc eht no nwod ti deppals qcaJ
/ ,ksam ym no tup I nehw
,ediserif eht / ta emoh ta leef yam I
”…neht ,seirots eht ni
.emit doog ekam yehT
– hgiels eht morf enog si thgiew eht sa noos sa dnA
,elbissop neve ,elbuort taht
.renosirp a saw ehs
,liat trohs reh fo hctiwt eht gniton
,gnineve ylzzird a otni gninrut yad trohs eht dna nehctik eht ni rehtegot ysub htob meht htiw ,won thgir taht nialpxe ot detnaw adnariM ”.semitemoS“
”!tey em etalutargnoc
.oot delims ysiaD ”…kniht t’ndid I tub
.revlover ytsurt sih werd qcaJ
,sgniw yredwop sih daerps tuanortsa ehT  ereh llew eb lliw lla dnA  .slias s’pihs llat a ni dniw ekil
.tnedicni eht troper ot xobllac ecilop tseraen eht drawot ffo detrats qcaJ
,sthgiltops tnecsednacni eht morf wolg lufrewop a gniwolloF
,tsegnol eht ecno ,raey yrevE
dekrims ssetnuoC ehT
.enrobria era yehT
.seciov gnimoclew dna ,ekoms fo semulp
…tsuj s’tI“ ”.uoy rof melborp a“
erif eht no gol rehtona gnittup htiw deipucco oot ton saw flowsedart ehT
”.kcab sih gnihctaw enoemos s’ereht wonk ot doog s’tI
,stnirptoof fo liart a ylno saw ereht tnemom a retfA
.htaerb sih rednu derettum eh ”,ledrob leuQ“ .srae sih ni dezzub snopaew citamotua fo raor eht sa
woc nietsloH hsilived a
.retniw saw nopaew esohw eof ythgim a tsniaga tabmoc elgnis ni saw tI
,erif rehtona eb syawla
,nwo reh ward dluoc ehs dehsiw adnariM
,noitasrevnoc fo cipot eht saw eh dezilaer yltnerappa flow eht ”,hu ,hO“
laets ot denrael dah ehs rof ,desolc detfird seye s’rehsaD
.llet ot tuoba saw eh yrots eht tuoba
,tsal ta sdrow eht denommus rehsaD
,pu ekops nogard enipluv desserd-llew eht ”,lleW“
,seod eh sa noos sa dna
.meht erahs ew ,meht tcelloc ew
,gnitirw ton s’ehs nehw tsacdoP slaminA egnartS stsoh ohw
,niaga dna niaga ,taog eht fo epahs eht deniltuo ehS
,llaH retraC eeneR yb snoitubirtnoc htiw
”.maerd ruoy s’ti sa gnol sa“
,drows yloh a htiw sdog eht yb desselb neeb dah roirraw tsetaerg riehT“
,dloc erew straeh riehT
.roreuqnoC ehT saw eseht fo tsomeroF
,nalC esooG eht ,nalc enO
,seires reveroF seipleK eht setirw ohw
.dnalrednow retniW
’.yrots gnitseretni na saw erus
.potfoor gnipols hcae tsniaga
?gnos ni rehtegot desiar ,seciov erom ro owt yna fo dias eb emas eht ton dluoC
”!sknahT“ .dias ysiaD
.reh raeh t’ndid dna ssertsimtsop eht ot gniklat ydaerla saw lerriuqs eht tub ,dias adnariM
.slaog s’raey txen fo klat reh ot denruter tibbar eht ,gniyrd adnariM htiw ,pu dehsaw ysiaD sA
”?sgniteem fo stros eseht fo“
.allerauqsaP oznecniV yb detide dna
:laer yllohw ton gnihtemos demeeS
.retniw fo tser eht rof doowerif hguone htiw dekcats ydaerla saw rebmahc ecnartne s’worrub reh hguoht neve ,gnildnik erom gnirehtag ruoh na tneps dna emoh deirruh ehS
,noillats eht deniatniam ”,llitS“
”.gnihtemos snaem boj ruO“ ”.dlot
.tfos erew seye reh tub
.sevolg yvaeh hguorht neve swap rieht dnuof selkcirp eht sa tnemtneser-flah ,rethgual-flah htiw gnituohs
,dedulcnoc gnos eht sa nevE  dloh ew snoinapmoc eht ,raeh ew taht eciov eht / :yroeht ni ylno fi / ,eb raen lla su tel oS
”!flesruoy fo erac ekaT !hctac ot
.elbanigami roloc yreve fo
.emit fo edistuo ecalp A
.lufthguoht gnikool ,dias ysiaD ”,taht tuobA“
.nug enihcambus nospmohT a gniraeb hcae ,snoog erom ruof denommus ehcaVaL
.trofmoc rof esolc oot hcum
seye krad esoht otni ezag ot ,eerf eb ot
”.ecnavda sih pots ton did tub esuap mih evag semalf eht did semit eerht
derevocsid tsrif ehs nehw raey eht fo skniht rehsaD dna
,seirraH nomoloS yb daer ”,flowcaM boR“ yb
.eno regral s’adnariM ni mraw wap mils reh
”.tey lla meht draeh t’nevah uoY“
.yawa decnalg eh nehw
,enigami thgim uoy sA
lla retfa ,netfo t’nsaw tI
,epahs kcalb ynob eht dnuora detsiwt dna delcric sthguoht reh ,sraey roF
gnici éhcâm-reipap htiw esuoh daerbregnig xuaf a tsniaga pu flesmih gnisserP
?regdab ydobemoh a naht sdneirf gnitseretni erom dedeen tibbar citsitra na taht reh gnillet fo yaw s’ysiaD siht saW
.ylevisnefed oot elttil a dias rehsaD ”,t’nod I“
.dias ysiaD ”,raey siht segnahc emos ekam ot gniog m’I“
spmal teerts nori thguorw tnecsednacni eht tuo gnitoohs yllacigetartS
,edisni deunitnoc ti ,nepo ti deppilf ehs nehW
,daor eht fo elddim eht ni yltpurba deppots taht
,revlover sih fo ttub eht gnisU
.suovren hguoht sa meh s’norpa reh gnitsiwt reh deciton dna ysiaD ta decnalg ehS
,erew ew taht thguoht I sseug I“
.niaga nees eb ot reven
,eciov tfos eht
.syawla sa ,tsrif ydaer si ehS
.thginot wons on si erehT
.eci fo sraeps htiw demra erew yehT
,seirots egnahcxe ot nageb yeht sA
.sdnoces ni niaga etihw saw tI
.rood tnorf eht fo noitcerid eht morf pmuht a saw ereht tnemom a retfA .god a fo
.meht rof elttab dluoc redael rieht nehw eugra ton dluow
,yldetcepxenu rehtaR
edir a tog ev’I ,yawynA
”.taht did seirots rehto eht fo enoN“
.snettim lufroloc dna
.srenroc tuc ot deen gnisserp-reve eht dna ,ytilibisiv orez ,spotfoor ycI
”?gnorw gnihtemos sI“  .2 fo 2 traP
,snoynac tresed eht morf raf
”.emas eht lla ,yrots a fo lleh a rof ekam lliW“
.esir yehT .llup yehT
.nugdnah 6091 NF derewoprednu s’regit eht morf derif stellub eht pots ot reirrab doowdrah eht desu qcaJ
,roirraW taht fo yromem eht knaht dna
”?reliam eht tuoba ereh m’I
.edistuo ria eht ni egnahc a detceted adnariM
.gniog erif a tuohtiw reillihc erew smoor rehto eht ecnis ,elbat nehctik llams eht ta tas yehT
?wonk uoy ,sretcarahc owt otni teews eht dna rettib eht detartnecnoc tsuj tI“
,deerga noinapmoc ediserif eht ,saw tI
,eceip evitaroballoc a fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
– maet reednier eht sa yromem eht otni stfird ehS
erew seirots detubirtnoC .2 fo 2 traP
,keew tsal sehcnarb radec dna ylloh morf shtaerw edam dah ysiaD dna ehS
,deffins dna eson reh detfil rehsaD
.deb ot og ot rekop eht edisa tes eh neht dnA
’.yenom‘ yas dluoc eh erofeb ffo mih tuc deraJ tub ,flow eht nageb
raey siht od ot gniog m’I sgniht eht fo eno
,ti fo demaerd s’ehs ,shtnom evlewt roF
.reh fo thgis eht ta feiler ni dezeeuqs tsehc s’rehsaD
dna rettib htiw detrats su fo tser ehT“
,dellac adnariM ”?emoh uoy erA“
.htaed rieht fo rennam dna ecalp eht syawla wonk ot saw esruc eht
?ereht gnivom wodahs a ees ehs seoD
,emarf ynob a dah ehS
.semitemos ,yenruoj eht ni pu thguac
.teef sih ot tog ,efarac eht yawa devaw flow eht ”,uoy knaht ,on tuB
.tuo derettug ,ssenesolc lautum fo taeh eht deined
”,yenom ni tnemyap rof ksa t’now uoy fI“
?os kniht t’nod I“
/ ,hguorht nellaf s’nalp eht nehW
elkna s’xnyl eht dnuora koorc eht depparw qcaJ
,erofeb raey eht ebyam ,raey tsal ebyam
.ecalp rieht nekat dah—
nrecnoc a dessefnoc meht fo eno
,eniltsaoc nretsew eht deflugne drazzilb drocer A
worbeye na dekcoc ahsiM
stius yarg hsa ni snoog fo riap a sa evom eht no ydaerla saw qcaJ ”!syob ,mih teG
.eriatnemélé elocé ni emit sih gnirud slipup eht denilpicsid ohw
eciov eht dehsiniF
.retteb neve saw wonS
.saw tsuj eh erehw raen erehwyna t’nsi taht
,enorht s’lëoN erèP ot gnidael euneva eht denil taht
.semag gniyalp dna gniltsoj era srehto ehT
,enola meht tem nalC mussopO eht fo roirraW ehT
”.oot aococ erom em teg uoy fi“
”.worrub ruoy rof ekam nac uoy sgniht etuc eht lla fo kniht tsuJ !elffiP“
elitcejorp a morf sretnilps htiw detlep saw eh sa eerf drows s’erugif eht erot yaj eulb ehT
.dias adnariM ”,stfarc ta doog yrev ton m’I“
rehsaD .drazzilb eht edisni morf ekops eciov tfos A
redaol deeps a desu qcaJ sa
.ecnad reh sekam ecneitapmI .eerf eb ot
.noisired s’taog eht fo ecaf eht ni wolloh gnar yeht tub
,retto teivoS emosdnah sih
,redluohs sih revo dekool flow ehT
.rekihhctiH flowereW eht ot
.sroirraw retniw eht fo gnissap eht tuo tiaw ot nihtiw pu sevlesmeht laes ot denimreted yehT
sdlrow suonidutitlum fo sgniod eht dna sdneirf tnesba fo degnahcxe swen dna
”.gnihtemos tuoba deirrow tsuj m’I“
.thgin saw ti edistuO
,sksut ybbuts sih rof dezis ksam iks a
”?ereh tuo gniod uoy era lleh eht tahW ?qcaJ“
.denruter gnirps ylwols dna
.mih ediseb tlah a ot dehceercs nades 701-LIZ edam-teivoS a
.yrd seog htuom reh dna
”,yug wen eht gnirussaer rof sknahT“
.amrI deerga ”,t’now eruS“
.erutaerc-flah tenretni ruoy ,anueL yb daer
,erots tnemtraped eht otni kcab kool evitruf a gnikaT
,tnew eh erehw ,saw eh revehcihW
”,yrt ot truh t’ndluoc ti esoppus I“
.netfo sdnalhgih tresed eht ni wons t’ndid tI
,seirots erom dna
”!reverof sdneirf tseb er’eW“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,emit gnol a rof uoy ksa ot detnaw ev’I .taht ekil d’I“
/ ksa ot hcum oot ti sI
.sserac eltneg a si drazzilb eht ,thginoT
.flowsedart eht dedda ”,dael eht ni s’eh yas d’I“
.ti fo eerf pils ot snaem ehs fi yrassecen si ti esuaceb siht derudne sah ehS
,ti koot ysiaD dna tuo wap reh dleh ehS
.sdrazzilb yb delbuortnu yks tesnus
dah ysiaD ,nevo ni saw ekac eht emit eht yB ”.norpa na s’ereH
.fooh eno depmats rehsaD
,deggurhs eh ”,wonk I“
,dias tibbar ehT
”,tnaw I erehw og I“
,sdog rehto yb yas emoS
.htmraw rof flesmih otni knirhs ot deirt regdaB ehT
”.ti ekam dluoc uoy doog oS !uelBeL ruetcepsnI“ ”!tialp suov li’s ,edia’l ed siaremia’J ?enoynA“
.ylloh fo sdnalrag dna
.swodahs eht morf tuo deppets
uoy knahT dna ,syadiloH yppaH
”,ereht ,pukcip eht no wolpwons eht detnuom I ,lleW“ ”!olluh“
,emmoS eht ta gnithgif eht fo tsrow eht gnirud enod d’eh ekil tsuJ
,emoc dah yeht sa ylsuoiretsym sa
kcarc prahs a htiw kcol niahc eht dehsams yaj eulb eht
– thginot – ydaer si ehS
”-yna evah yltcaxe t’nod I“
.yaw gnorw eht ruf eht gnibbur
.aet erom htiw ekac eta neht ,dekab ekac eht elihw aet knard dna deklat yehT .dehgual ysiaD ”.pu su dengis ydaerla I esuaceb ,dooG“ .dias adnariM
.ylwols oot nwolf
nwod flesmih werht qcaJ
.suominanu saw ti llit
”-tub ,taht htiw gnorw gnihton s’ereht dna ,teews yreV
,gninrub si erif a erehwemos steg eh nehw tuB“
rettam ekil sgniht naht yaw tnereffid a ni laer ,spahrep ro
.won ti htiw enod si ehs tub
.yrrow fo gnap a ni
,foor eht morf tpael dna delkcuhc ylno taog ehT
gniteeM ediseriF“   ,yojne esaelP
.ereh teg ot did I tahw ,od ew tahw gniod
gnidaer neeb d’ehs kcabrepap snekciD eht tuhs eltsimocac eht ”?deraJ ,uoy tahT“
dor deppit-latsyrc a htiw derutseg ssetnuoC ehT
,flowerew eht litnu ,hcae htiw tcatnoc eye edam regdab ehT
,dettimda flowerew eht
.seno ylacs sih xofnogard eht
.ot eelf ot htuos erom on dnuof dna dne s’dlrow ot emac yeht nehw neppah dluow tahw deraef yeht hguohT
,dessap ti nehw dna
.dnuorg eht evael ot tsrif ,secart eht otni tsriF
”?thgir ,uoy saw taht
.reh tsniaga segrahc fo tsil eht ot dda tsael ta dluoc eh
,tekcaj tius sih fo tekcop renni eht morf nioc cnarf-001 dlog a gnihsiF
.drawrof flesreh sworht rehsaD dna ,sdnuos eltsihw ehT
,rehtegot swap dettops-kcalb reh gnippalC
.thgin eht rof pu esolc ot rehtehw gnitabed saw ehS
– dna setatse otni ylkciuq daerps sesuoh eht dna ,kcab spots ruof dniheb ytic eht tfel d’yehT
”,nam ,doog on od t’now reh htiw gniugrA“
”!ssenisub ot kcab teg s’teL ?txen s’ohW !woN“ ,mih derussa eh
,xof cinocard eht dias ”,lleW“
.sgnos tuohtiw yadiloh a eb t’ndluow ti esruoc fo dnA
.smraf – yllautneve
tuoba saw draeh I yrots ehT
.rood edicius raer eht nepo werht ohw ahsiM saw ti
,neppah yeht erehw ,morf emac seirots eht erehw saw dlrow ehT“ .dehgis regdab ehT
.mraw yllacitsiretcarahcnu
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
ni deraeppa lla ereh detneserp seirots ehT
,eelf ot hguone tfiws ton saw
,werdhtiw tsoh dloc eht dna
”,tniop elohw eht taht t’nsI“ ”.enim dnA“
.eelf ot denimreted saw
,roolf eht ot gnirettalc lotsiP
,erusnu dednuos remrahc eniuqe eht ”,yas t’nac I“
,snolat sih neewteb dehctulc tnemesitrevda evitsef eht ta drawnwod gnicnalG .xiaP al ed euR ,2 ,sserdda detats eht ta gnidliub gnimussanu eht fo ecnartne eht hguorht deppets
,ecnavda ni noitanalpxe na deraperp dna ,tnemugra s’tep eht gniyalper neeb d’ehs ,shtnom evlewt roF
denrut seye lla woN
eb dluoc taht sdlrow eht ni
.daehrevo niar fo rettap eht draeh adnariM
”tsaeF yadiloH eht retfA gniteeM ediseriF“ saw sihT   .emit rehtona
ocomA 75 etuoR ehT morF ssorcA reniD kcirC elbbeP eht fo pihsroteirporp esnesnon-on reh rof ytnuoC ajebA tuohguorht nwonk saw zedeneM amrI  ”.ees ll’ew dna“ ,remrahc eniuqe eht dereffo ”,ti llet uoy tuoba woH“
erif gnirevoc nwod dial eh ,ecalp otni kcab rednilyc eht gnippanS
.tsoh sih dna roreuqnoC ehT fo retniw eht tlem ot hguone toh eb dluow semalf eht ebyam rof ,egaruoc roirraw eht evag sihT
”,eerga t’nod I lleW“
,llew sa noititepmoc morf seirots rieht dna sevlesmeht desucer lla—
,ti eveileb nac uoy fi ,gnikihhctiH
.thgin eht otni tuo dekool flowerew eht
.ssenrah dna sparts fo tnemtsujda na
.llafwons hserf htiw gnillif ylwols
”?tahw roF“ ”…detiaw ylno I
,retfa retniw yreve
taR .noitcerid s’noog eht ni
,srehtaef s’qcaJ delffur tsalb yci na sA
.egaw sraw elituf nehw cimednap fo semit ni / cimelop lufraef dna / cimetsys ecitsujnI ega etarepsed a no eud eb ll’tner eht dna /
eert samtsirhC laicifitra na dniheb gnikcuD
”.gniwons s’ti kniht I“
,noinipo reh ni ,noitalsnart hsinapS tseb eht ton—
depirtsnip a ni niuqennam a dniheb denoitisop reed ksum a—
.meht tuoba leef I woh elpoep llet si
.tixe erif edis eht drawot gniknils erofeb
?ruojnoB“  .nageb eh erofeb
.erofeb ereht dethgila reven d’ehs hguoht
,sllihtoof depard-wons lufecaep yal edistuO
”.oot deppots s’niar ehT
.ssalg fo sdrahs esiouqrut htiw dedduts skeehc sih gnivael
,cigam eht ni thguac
.ynohpocac yrotcaflo na otni dedolpxe mih dnuora noitces emufrep ’seidal eht sa
”!ehcaVaL ,yppols gnitteg er’uoY ?snoog owt ylnO“
”?yaw taht leef reve uoy oD“
.flesreh ehs naht
.rettib rof etsat hcum evah I dnif t’nod I“
.rehto hcae ta derats yehT
.dias rehsaD ”,tep a er’uoY“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ediserif eht ekil ecalp a hcaer dluoc
”,tnaw I erehw og I“
”.lliw uoy fi ehcuob-esuma erem A
.adnariM dessap ehs sa yprihc saw eciov s’tuntsehC .sM
,sgnirts norpa reh denethgit dna detrons ehs ”?tluciffiD“
,allerauqsaP oznecniV ,wahS .C.K ,kcobnegeiZ
.thgin eht rof rood sih tuhs god eht tsal ta dnA
.noitanimreted gnihcnilfnu htiw noitcartta edisdaor eht ot yaw eht del rehsaD
”ygolohtnA samtsirhC noitciF hsalF yrruF A !syadilwoH yppaH“
,sllaw eht gnihsillebme
regnol dnoces tilps a elbisiv saw seye s’tacyella eht fo eulb DEL ehT
tegrat sih tops ot ssalg dehsilop eht ffo noitcelfer eht gnisU
.erom gnihtemos si kniht I
txen strats ssalc ehT“
,wahS .C.K yb ”wonS“
”,ti tuoba yrrow t’noD“
’pu llup rac a raeh t’ndid I‘ ro
rednilyc s’revlover 2981 elèdoM sih deitpme qcaJ—tius
.dnuora swap yruolf reh gnivaw ,yllacitsaisuhtne deklat dna raey wen eht rof snalp fo lluf saw ehS
”.naelc ll’I ,dekooc uoY“
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daer
,gnituohs ysiaD yb yletaidemmi dewollof ,dekconk enoemos nehw nehctik eht ni rettab ekac gnixim saw regdab ehT
,stoob detalusni ylivaeh fo riap a fo secal eht htiw deltserw rekihhctih flowerew eht ”,lleW“ .denrut noinapmoc ediserif eht ”?tey enog toN“
.hguoht ,yruf rieht tlef ehS
,dedaf retniW .enog erew htob
.ecnelis dennuts ni desuap ocomA 75 etuoR ehT morF ssorcA reniD kcirC elbbeP ehT
.stfig tnaw t’ndid ehs demialc syawla ysiaD tub
”,tnavres a er’uoy dnA“
,snalc eerht esoht tuB
,snaem yranidro naht erom yb
,meht dewollaws semalf deroloc fo tsrub taerg A
”?!uelBeL ruetcepsnI taerg eht renroc dluoc uoy kniht yllaer uoy diD“
”.slleb fo gnirts yllis a yb retsam ruoy ot deiT“ .dias ehs
.tuanortsa eht demmuh
teprac loowsbmal eht otno deppord ssarb tneps fo eceip A
.roreuqnoC eht fo daeha yats ot eb deen sa
tser eht lla ,flowsedart eht ,tacyella eht ,tuanortsa eht—eno yb eno nehT
.neppah reven dluow taht wenk ehs
.sehcnarb detsud-sotsebsa neewteb tuo dekeep qcaJ sa
.seirots doog er’yeht“
.llifer eeffoc a htiw drawrof gninael ,dias amrI
ecalp emos ot evael nac eh
”,drac ruoy tog I“ .lufituaeb
seenk dna smraerof sih no ekil-yrtnafni delwarc qcaJ
.ti fo eerf dna dlrow eht edistuo gnihtemos
.sedalb s’rehto hcae nopu degrahc rereuqnoC ehT dna roirraW ehT ,tsal tA“
/ tnemom a rof tsuj tahT
,god.ecioveht ta
,etorw tsuj ehs yllaniF
yawrood dethgil ,nepo eht ni doots noinapmoc ediserif ehT ”!syadiloh yppaH“
,hguone deppord erutarepmet eht fi tub
.eno esrow a nees d’yeht ecnis neeb dah ti gnol woh
,detaeper taog eht
,purys tub etalp sih no gnihton saw ereht ecno detpurretni flow eht
,erom ecnad ot gniog m’I“
*** .enog saw taog eht dna
.gnihton dias dna seye krad reh otni derats rehsaD
.tsitra na t’nsaw ehs ysiaD ekilnu tub
,nageb eh erofeb tuB
redluohs s’rekcarctun eht hguorht erot taht
,muirta suoicaps eht revo demool taht mroftalp eznorb dedlig a no gnidnatS
.derettulf traeh reH
”?ereh pu teg uoy did woH“
,ereht yrots a sllet eh
,ria llihc eht sllif srehto eht fo htaerb ymaets ehT
foor eht fo egde eht ot ecnarp lliw ehS
.ybbat yarg eno dna ocilac eno ,tnorf eht no snettik fo riap a htiw drac etuc a no delttes ehS
,dessap thgin tsedloc
,erocs yksvokiahcT a fo yhtrow rekcarctun a dniheb gnilloR
.sduolc eht tuo gnitniop swalc ekil gnikool sehcnarb eert erab htiw ,etihw saw yks ehT
,nwardhtiw dah srats ehT
maerd lliw ehS .pael dna
”.stnuoc eno taht fi wonk t’nod I ,hO“  ”.ees og s’teL“
,tnilf no leets ekil ,semalf kraps dluow ria eht hguorht gnuws nehw hcihw
.erif no si meht woleb dlrow eht fi sa seilf dna
eht dnuof tsuj ev’I kniht I tuB“
,saw mrotswons eht dab woh detabed amrI dna deraJ
eerf eno deggut qcaJ
.wons eht hguorht nruhc sgel reH
?ti enigami ylno ro repsihw eht raeh ehs seoD
,raey siht htrib a neeb dah erehT
.htron nezorf eht morf nwod dehcram tsoH dloC eht ,oga sega ynaM“ :nageb flow eht
,semalf eht sa krad tnew moor ehT
”.etaf ruoy tpecca tseB“ .dias anilevaj eht
.semalf deroloc-ynam htiw gnizalb drows
.eton lufepoh a no
.sediserif eseht ta ylno dehcuot taht
.sdrac gniteerg fo noitceles eht desworb ehS .ton depoh ehS
.flow eht ta yllacitirc dekool amrI ”!rehtaew siht ni
.kaeuqs detum a htiw roiretni rehtael suoiruxul eht otni deppils dna
,htuos rehtruf dna rehtruF
…elttil a teg I sseug I“
”.oga sruoh wef a ti tnes tsuj I ?ydaerlA“
.ylluferac ria dloc eht deffins adnariM ,emoh yaw reh nO
.dloc saw doolb rieht
wap s’retto eht koot qcaJ
.evots doow nori tsac eht pu erif ot dah amrI rehtehw saw ,denimreted yeht ,hcihw fo erusaem elpicnirp ehT
.hguoht ,eno txen eht yb tuo dnuof evah ll’I ebyam“
.erif eht trapa dekconk dna
”?em tuoba seirots gnillet ereht tuo elpoep s’ereht fi tahW“
.noitacided yramotsuc reh htiw ssenrah reh otni denael rehsaD
noisacco eht kram ot dnuoforp
*** ”.ytterp etiuq er’uoy ,og stnavres sa tuB“
,nur ot ydaer si rehsaD dna ,reh teem ot tuo spets wodahs ehT .maerd nwo reh
”,reednieR“ .dias ehs ”,taoG“
*** .enil otni spets – yllanif
,gnihtyna naht ssenetilop desufnoc fo tuo erom
.mih ta deknilb htob yehT
.gniliec eht fo srenroc eht dnuora gnurts sthgil samtsirhC eht ta pu gniddon
qcaJ erofeb tsuj
”tsaeF yadiloH eht retfA
”?siht ekil thgin a no tuo gniod ereh dneirf ruoy dna uoy s’tahw ,sekaS“
,noitcif trohs rof noissap a htiw yenrotta na
srotcepsorp dlog knurd-maerd ,dehsirevopmi fo doolf eht rof erots lareneg a neeb dah gnidliub siht nehw syad eht fo gnimaerd—
.gniht gnorw eht dias d’ehs diarfa saw ehs hguoht sa ,raef htiw demmir-etihw erew seye nworb s’ysiaD
.soahc eht dima ydaets ,sloop krad ,eguH
.rennid yadiloh a retfa ecalperif eht dnuora
”.yaw ym no saw I emiT“
.wons ot nrut thgim ti
,deunitnoc taog eht ”,naem I“
.gnik a saw eh dias emoS
,meht ssentiw neve ro seirots dnif ew ,ekiL ?etarapes …ekil
ereh llewd ew yam gnol dnA  .eno yb eno
”.gnidne yppah a meht evag neht dnA
.sthgilf neewteb tser fo tnemom hcae
.nur ot snaem ehs fI
.sdog dna sgnik neewteb ecnereffid elttil tub saw ereht erehw sega eht erew eseht ,kniht I ,yas
.wodahs a ekil thgin eht otni gnihsinav
mih tsap goj snoog eht tel qcaJ
,ecno meht ekil saw ehs srebmemer rehsaD
.deticxe dednuos flowerew ehT ”!gnorts ytterp s’taht ,hO“  .reverof
.reh ta deknilb rehsaD
,deddon amrI nehw tuB
.dnuora teg I ,hO“
.troppus ni derevihs maet eht ,ti deticer ehs nehW
,rae lacizziuq a desiar noinapmoc ediserif eht
yas dluoc meht fo rehtie erofeB
,thguoht ot ekops ehs enoyreve fi derednow adnariM
.foor eht pota gnieb ssenisub on dah taht lamina na fo eniltuo eht tuo gnikcip ,deknilb
tniA“,ecnelis eht ekorb deraJ ,yllaniF
*** .noitresed fo smaerd redael rieht elihw niaga pots dna trats dna pots yehT
,lanrete gnihtemos
,devirra pukcab emit eht yb snosniktA tfel evah yldetbuodnu dluow ehcaVaL ssetnuoC hguohtlA
”,em ot niar ekil sllems tI“
.ti tuoba suoires saw ti ,did ti nehw tuB
.no degar drazzilb ehT
redloh ragic dlog tarak-neethgie na ot nward ylevitcnitsni saw eh
meht dniheb ynomrah eht yb yenruoj txen rieht no delleporp ,enog erew yeht
.redluohs s’regdaB eht no wap a detser noinapmoc ediserif ehT .ffo deliart eh
”.tnavres a llits si tnavres A“
enil otni spets rehsaD
.yadiloh eht ot pu gnidael tnemeticxe eht derreferp ehS .reh derob
”.em seirrow taht gnihtemoS
!radnelac tnevda eht fo wodniw tsrif eht ylerem saw tahT“
tuo gnigrahc erofeb
elttil eht sa raf sa tub ,nosaes eht fo yletinifed yrev dna ,erus ,nuF
.tsael ta paehc tub
.syadiloh rof ysiaD dneirf reh teg ot tahw wenk reven ehS
,retnuoc eht ta taes a koot ,flow eht tsap deppets deraJ
sevooh tilps ynit reh ecalp ot tsriF
,htaerb peed a koot rekihhctih flowerew eht ”,taht sI“ ”.uoy
egamulp sih laecnoc ot pu ralloc sih werd yaj eulb eht
.dias ehs ”,raey ym si siht ekil leef I“
.revoc retteb rof gnilbmarcs snoinapmoc sih gnidnes ,niuqennam eht otni revo delppot reed ksum ehT !tat-tat-
,kcab dna pu ylffits devruc kcen reH
”,modeerf fo maerd I“ .seye krad esoht dna
”.gniticxe oot gnihton s’ti ,hO“
;tabmoc ni roreuqnoC ehT decaf yeht semit eerhT
.gniteem htruof rieht no dias taog eht
.ffo taoc hcnert sih detsud qcaJ elihw
”.lla retfa ,ereht tuo dloc s’tI
.lla ta taht ni rettib gnihtyna ees I sa“
.fooh tilps hcae fo evruc eht dna ,skcoh reh fo kcab eht ta ruf yggahs eht
,oot nellaf s’epoh lla dna
.pu mraw dna tis uoy ;eugra t’nod uoy ,oN
srodo larolf dna ksum fo egnalém gnirewoprevo ehT
.nap eht ruolf dna esaerg nac uoY“ ”?pleh I naC
…kniht I ,ssorca nar I eno ehT
d’erehT .gniwolg dna ,deknab owt ro rebme na tfel eh tuB
.tsehc sih gnissorcssirc sepirts eht ta thgiarts
”.wols era sregdaB .eciov wols a sah ehs esruoc fO“
.eson sih hguorht dehgis rekihhctih eht ”,eniF“ ”!sruoy dnA“
,dekcor hgiels eht ,foor eht tsniaga dedduht yvaeh gnihtemos tuB
!allef siht was I nehw daor noynac eht nwod gnimoc saw I
!ladicius thgirnwoD“
,snopaew degde htiw delliks saw eh hguohT
yenruoj reh fo dne eht ta esimorp eht sleef ehS
,retniw ni tsol neeb dah ohw esoht lla erew yeht roF
”.nwod kcab egaruoc s’roirraW ehT tuc siht
”?yenoh ,eno taht raeh uoy d’erehW“
”!gnippohs evE samtsirhC ym tpurretni uoy erad woH“
”…uoy rof tfig samtsirhC tcefrep
.redluohs s’regit eht fo taem eht decreip ti taht os ediw drows eht gnidnes
”!yawa gnitteg s’eH“
,god eht derewsna ”,erus m’I nehT“
.secirp elas erif ta
.taorht reh ni traeh reh htiw enilfoor eht revo ezag deirrow a gniggard dna gnidnecsed ,srevihs ehs ,llitS
llafwons sseltneler ,eltneg ,tfos fo dnik eht dna
,citatsce dna tnednecsnart gnihtemos demees ,rehtegot ,seciov ehT  ?eeht htiw rehtegot tub enola
’.dab ytterp‘ saw tcidrev eht—
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb daer