.tnemom a rof tnelis saw hploduR ”.mM“ ”.haey …lleW“
”,yrots ruo nesohc ydaerla evah lla ll’ew ,tuB“
.taht dnatsrednu nac I“
.deneppah dah tahw dezilaer ehs sa htuom reh derevoc ehS .yldas dias eh
.srae sih dekcirp god
.ti htiw gnihtemos od ot elba eb ot ekil tsuj d’I .yllaer toN“
.emit eht lla ti ees I“
”.ytrap yadiloh a ot gnirb uoy gniht adnik eht t’nia
.ni tfard a gnittel
.mih ta yltnatcepxe deralg dna
”.elpoep spleh taht gnihtemoS .did uoy ekiL
”.ylrae pu gnittuhs fo gnikniht saw I ,ni llup uoy was I erofeb ,tcaf nI .teiuq yllaer
?seno lufroloc eht ekil uoY !hA“
”.wonk uoy ,tnorf eht ni emoc“
.nwod sgnot eht tup dna
erif a nehw sthgin emos era ereht
,rood tnorf yreve revo
.rac ym detratser dna ,taoc ym ffo deggurhs I ,deruces eeffoC
.tneitap eb nac I
,em tsuj saw ti ,esiwrehtO
”?seillub wef a gnippaz ot drawrof gnikooL“
,taoc sih revo hsaw sroloc eht gnittel
”—it rehtona siht od ew t’naC
flesmih rof wons hserf revo sitsap esruoc fo dna
”?neht ,og ot rehtruf hcuM“
.mih ot llac ot demees sevaw tfos rieht dna
.dnuow a denepo dah anafeB aL tub
”.doog gnihtemos evresed nerdlihc ehT
.peels ot ffo gnitfird flesym tlef I ,ecno naht eroM .gnihtyna fi
,evac eht ssorca swalc fo tes gnikrow eno htiw flesmih llup ot gnitaicurcxe saw tI
sessalg dna setalp naelc emos dehctef dna
,tiusecaps a ni htom a deksa
”!nerdlihc sih deviltuo eH“
.ybab eht hctaw rO
”,noitidart tsuj s’taht ,lleW“
,fo erac ekat ot sbuc htiw stneve ot tuo teg ot drah s’ti“
.gof eht ni hgiels eht ediug ot uoy deksa atnaS nehW“ ”?tahw oD“
.noitseuq eht fo tuo etiuq
.thgilerif eht ni dekniw nworc delewej a erehw
.noom eht fo thgil raelc eht yb demarf erew setteuohlis rieht
,dias dna flesreh demlac ehs tub
.taorht sih deraelc
…taht htiw od ot gnihton ,rehtie ,emag
,srelletyrots eseht fo eno gnilbuort s’tahw tuo dnif ot
,deworruf sworbeye no-nward rieht
.woleb roolf enots eht otno gnikalf dna
.evac eht fo tuo yaw reh no gnibbos ylteiuq
pots ot yrt ll’I .evird yrarbil eht rof koob a evah I“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.daeha pu noitats sag a saw ereht ,ylikcuL
,gnihtyreve eerht
?steknirt ruoy reviled uobirac yletirps taht tonnaC ?em ksa yhW“
.emoh fo gnos a pu kcurts riohc a ,kroY weN ni yawa seliM
”.uoy ees I nehw ti eveileb ll’I“ ,deddon naoM hanniS ”.yb
.ylfeirb seye sih desolc elgniJ
,ereh gnieb yojne od I tuB
,seirots setirw dna semag sekam ohw
.ereh dekool gnihtyreve tnereffid woH
nu fo dnik tnereffid a tog s’ti kniht I tub ,rettib thgirtuo sa ton s’eno sihT
.drazzilb eht ni teef ydaets no doots eh sa
.yrekab cificeps-yadiloh a ton saw staerT s’lesniT
”,ti no teb d’I“
.sdneirf ym rof ti did I ,yltsom tuB“
,smlap htob neewteb ylregnig deppuc ro seenk no decnalab erew sknird ,dellif erew setalP
.noillats eht ot nerdlihc sih fo—
”.enog saw siht nehw
enoemos ot klat ot dah tsuj I“
”.dnatsrednu dluoc ohw enoemoS .tnereffid—
,taoc sih revo dehsaw sevaw eulb dna neerg gniremmihs
.decnivnoc ton saw reyerF
shpargotohp dewohs regdab ehT
.drow yreve delwoh I
yraew yllufetarg
s’reveohW“ .pu ekops rekihhctih flowerew eht
,no evord I sa dnA
.aH ?enog ,selbuort ym llA
.xobrednit reh htiw ti til dna
.ot deen t’ndid I .ylper t’ndid I
stirips rieht mraw ot nerdlihc eht ot stneserp dna ydnac reviled ot hsiw I dna ,segar edistuo mrots ehT
,truocerof eht otni dellup I
thgilf tsrif sih nekat dah nos sih nehw yad eht derebmemer eH
.hguoht ,dluoc uoY
retaw otni detlem eci dna wons eht ylwolS
”,emit fo ytilibativeni teiuq eht ot noitangiseR“
.ecnelis ni aococ eht fo tsal eht dehsinif yehT
.taorht sih deraelc neht
.gninnuc s’tac a fo ygrene eht lla htiw enohs llits seye reh tub
”.raey fo emit siht dnuora yllaicepsE
.os ylbirret semitemoS“
,denrecnoc dednuos eH
.emit gnol a rof evah nerdlihc eseht yoj fo tib tsal eht eb yam sihT
.rebmun eht detekcop I ”.gnir a em evig
eht sgol eht fo tsrif eht ta kcil ot nageb semalf sA .laitnesse si
.rehto eht ot eno morf ecnalg a dessap elcric tilerif elohw ehT
.llah eht morf mih detpurretni sgniteerg desirprus fo dnuos eht rehtie ruop dluoc noinapmoc ediserif eht erofeb tub
,thgin teews ,dloc eht ni nocaeb a ekil
,enoyna fi ,ohw ees ot
.ecneserp gnitadimitni eht ot desu
,mrywkooB irikeneN ,iluaP secnarF
wons tfos eht otni dnah sih deppid eh
!oot noitidart ruo ,noitidart samtsirhc tsuj toN“
”.ytivitaN eht fo eve eht no tuo tes evah dluohs eh nehw oga syad wef a tsuj hcum sa em dlot eH
tuons cinocard sih dekcip ylsseltsil reyerF
”,wef a eb yam ereht gnileef a evah I“ ”?srehto ynam gnitcepxE“
”!remotsuc deulav a ot edur oS .woW“
.ti htiw ecaep rieht ekam dna gnihton evah lliw nerdlihc eht nehT“
.sdrow sih fo ytireves gnimees eht ot eil eht evag eciov siH
”…uoy erA“ ,dias eh ”,esaelP“
”?ereh krow uoy fo ynam woH“
.sgab eht debbarg xof ehT
.repap no gnihtemos gnilbbircs nep a fo dnuos eht yb sthguoht sih morf detcartsid saw lesniT
s’erehT .ot tnaw uoy fi ylnO“
”.seno der dna neerg esoht fo eerht dna
.nuh ,yad gnol a hcus neeb s’tI“
”.thginot gnilbbab yna raeh t’nod I“
,xof cinocard eht rof nomannic dna leep egnaro htiw dellum teralc fo elttob a fo tsal eht
.retniw ekil I ,lleW“
”…gnol taht tiaw t’nac uoy fi ,tuB
.ksa ot won yllis demees ti tuB
,hguoht ,nosaes elbatiforp tsom sih gnieb morf retniw pots t'ndid tI
,esac yalpsid yrtsap a dniheb doots reednier eht
.ees ,ereh pu elbailer eroM
”,dab ton er’yeht sseug I“
yah fo stsiwt wef a dna sekac-ssom htiw lehctas a dekcap reednier gnuoy ehT
”?ereh tuo ylenol teg uoy t’noD .hO“ ”.em tsuJ“
”!ereht gnitteg s’eh tub mih no hguor neeb s’ypareht lacisyhP“
,hcits-yb-hctits ,tuo dekcip ylgnikatsniap aingisni eht lla htiw
”.niT ,lausu sa tcefreP .seY“
”!txen og ot gnireetnulov s’enoemos ekil“
.pu em gnar reihsac ehT
”.syadiloh eht rof yllacificeps esoht edaM
?krow llits neve yeht diD
.tuohguorht yarg dna revlis fo sehctap htiw kcalb tej saw ruf reH
siht tuoba ton dnA“
,snoitcerid ddo ni delknirc dna gnol erew sreksihw reH
,wodniw yreve dnuora ,ecnef yreve
,seldoodrekcins nezod a
noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf dna tsoh rieht gnivael
.etuc rehtar kool mih edam – tsenoh m’I fi
gnol eht dna ,sllih retniw dloc eht
.dnoyeb sdnal dliw eht otni peed
esac doow aslab detfarc ylsuolucitem egral a nwod tes flowsedart A ”,ces eno ,eruS“
morf emac eh erehw noitavonni wen ylevitaler a—
.nepo gnuws rood eht—
.yci dna psirc lla dlrow eht gniees ekil I
?yendoR htiw etad A
elims llams a mih evag yendoR ”.draC“
– edis rehtie no gnidnats eno
,krad sih hcihw tsniaga elzzum etihw a dna taoc deppit-yarg a dah ti dniheb reednier ehT
.gnigdurgeb emos ,tnemeerga fo srumrum lareneg erew erehT
.gnihtaerb sa ysae dna larutan
)nobanniC rof trohs( ynniC
.tellaw sih ni kcab drac sih tup eH
.rehtegot desserp spil rieht dna
,rehtegot dednelb tnimreppep dna eeffoC
yb snoitubirtnoc htiw
”.leef uoy yaw eht leef uoY .enif s’taht tuB
”…erofeb ecnis etad a no neeb t’nevah I“
.evac sih fo ecnartne eht hguorht deretne erugif a sa
flesmih ot delims lesniT ”!eyB“
”.tuo uoy ekat em tel d’uoy fi gniksa m’I“
”.gard ym nI .ereh ma I sa
”.doof eerf ta ecnahc a ssim reven I ,sediseB
”!niatniam ot egami na tog ev’I“
.reh morf yawa detniop
,stseug emac eseht retfA
,nosaer a rof etats enoggod taht tfel d’I
,daeh sih koohs sedart lla fo flow eht
.ecneserp s’enoyna kram ot tsud eht ni ereht dna ereh stnirpwap taerg tub gnihton htiw
’yloh‘ ro ,spahrep
xof cinocard eht dna
:retniw ruoy teg ll’uoy nehT
.drac tiderc sih mih gnidnah dna ti gninepo
,pis a koot I dna
.cigam yb delaecnoc saw ti erows srehto
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dehsiruonlam dna detardyhed saw ydob evissam siH
,enog eb noos selbuort ruoy lla yaM“  .nageb dna
selacs eulb sih ot denruter enihs dna retsul peed A
,seirugua eht daer evah I
emit txen ni enuT
.keew siht neve ro ,won thgir eb ot evah t’nseod tI“
ni deraeppa lla ereh detneserp seirots ehT .floWcaM boR dna ,allerauqsaP oznecniV ,wahS .C.K ,kcobnegeiZ
,wons fo esnapxe htooms eht ta mih fo daeha tuo dekool eh
,ecneh stnemom eht ni nerdlihc sih tuoba gnikniht pots ot deirt reyerF
.niaga rebmun eht ta nwod neht
.ekops eh sa elkcuhc tfos a tuo tel yendoR ”?tahW .yrros m’I“
.esaelp ,eeffoc a ekil d’I ,iH“
,nosaes a tsuj s’ti rebmemeR
”.seog gniyas eht sa ,sremmuB oN
.sillyhP siS rof daerbregnig nagev eht fo nezod-flah a dna
”tsaeF yadiloH eht retfA
.emoh kcab yaw eht lla mih ediug ot hguone thgirb gninihs
regdab gnikool-yhs a ”,lleW“
,aet teews a rof deksa noillats ehT
.ecnelis elbaturcsni ylbaffa sih deniatniam god eht tub
”.gnorw erew yeht ezilaer dna uoy tpecca meht sekam taht gnihtemoS“
.dnuor-raey mih dedivorp ellivniffirG tseW fo sklof eht troppus dna ssenildneirf eht detaicerppa lesniT dna
.rohtua eht yb daer
”.ereh noissimda fo ecirp on
,rednit tuo dial dna tlenk eh
,sevlehs dna selbat nedoow wef a htiw ,yzoc tub elpmis saw esuoh eht ,edisnI
.dnuora gnah ot tnaw t’ndid I ,llitS
.edirp htiw dennirg lesniT
ecneitap on ev’I“ .noitcerid reh ni detrons reyerF ”.rovaf a uoy fo ksa ot emoc ev’I ,anirB reyerF“ ,mih ta pu delims ehS
.noitats eht nar flow A
.retsaf elttil a taeb traeh s’lesniT edam
”.eno taht toN .yltcaxe ton
,worb sih deworruf yendoR
.tem erofeb t’ndah eh ereh eno ylno eht ,tacyella eht ot flesmih decudortni htom ehT
.denworf dna pu swap sih tup god redlo ehT
.seye eulb-eci sih teem ot tluciffid saw ti ,nosaer emos roF
.edisa gnidnats ,dias eh ”,ni emoC“
.delims eh sa spil sih hguorht dekeep hteet s’yendoR
.desolc saw noitats eht fi derednow I
”.emit ni emoc thgim tahT .melborp oN“
.yltfos delkcuhc neeuq ehT
moorb reh morf giwt a ffo ekorb ehS ”?demahsa uoy erA
gniht emas eht rof keew yreve ecno yrekab eht ot emac yendoR
.mih ta pu dezag reednier eht sa
os meht dlot d’eh yas ot tuoba saw noillats ehT
,gnitsalreve efil fo osla ma I“
?ton yhw ,sey dias I oS
psag a detareggaxe xof ehT
.ztlamhcs eht otni kcab thgiarts depmuj yeht ,gnos lamron eno retfa tuB
.rewop sih ot stimil sah eh nevE“
,eninac eht ta pu delims lesniT ”.yendoR ,yeH“
”.atnaS yllaicepsE
.hgis enipul ,peed a dehgis flow eht dna ,deddon I
.eson der gniwolg a dah I .era uoy ohw
.liam eht deirrac dah ehs nehw syad eht morf
.krad gnitteg saw yks eht dna
,leehw gnireets eht dehctulc I
,hO‘ ,woh tuoba uoy erutcel t’now I ,lleW“
,ssertnuH renniw drawA ltoyoC eht fo rohtua
erots eht denepo lesniT ecnis os gniod neeb dah dna
,pil sih tib dna retnuoc eht no drac s’yendoR deppat eH ”.wonk t’nod I“
”?yadot tiderc ro hsac gniod uoY“
,esion elttil a rof no oidar eht denrut ylno d’I
.thginot rof cigam elttil a tsuj“
,tsetnoc utpmorpmi rieht sniw
.flesruoy me‘ llet dna yb emoc tsuJ“
gab repap rellams a denepo eH
,eman gard ym yb em gnillac eb tseb uoY !yadiloH lesniT“
drehpehS namreG llat ehT
.ni lla og ot evah t’nod uoy
,lufecaep oot elttil A
.nalp eht saw tahT
.sedarT llA fo floW a ,traH ydrA yb daer
”?sniw ,dne eht ni ereht gnitteg llits elihw ,teews morf tsehtruf seog yrots
,delttes erew yeht retfa dias hploduR ”,woN“
,sthgileD s’retniW nezod A
.lwahs reh ta raet ot denetaerht dna
ruf s’god eht tsniaga wolg tfos a tsac sreltna s’lesniT ni sthgil ehT
.net llit gnimrofrep eb annog er’eW
,denepo srood tnorf dekcedeb-thgil eht fo enO
”!senob dna niks tub thguan era uoY
?yendoR emosdnah ,tnelis ,llaT
?eb eh dluoc esle ohw ,nwotsamtsirhC ni senac ydnac eht lla yB
.ereh ton s’ynniC .haeY“
.siht rof mih eraperp ot elttil did
,egattoc elttil taht morf daeha tsac wolg knip mraw a ees dluoc eh tnemom a rof thguoht eh
,elbat eht morf revo dellup sriahc nehctik no ,namotto eht no
,yks thgin eht otni ffo koot yeht dna
,devaw giw ednolb rieht morf riah ehT
niht repap sgniW
;evac llams sih edistuo tsuj gnigar mrotswons ythgim a saw erehT
.pu dekool dna hcae rof secirp eht ni deppat eH
.setalp eht fo eno no yekrut tsaor dna seikooc gnilip ylisub
,rood eht ta pu dekool lesniT
rebmun enohp eht ta derats lesniT sa niaga delims yendoR
”,rednetnoc gnorts a s’tI“ ”.eltbus yrev saw“
,segdeh eht dna sfoor eht derevoc wons hguohT
”,nerdlihc rieht eviltuo ohw esoht fo feirg eht si sihT“
”?evac ym ni ecneserp ruoy fo erusaelp eht ewo I od tahw ot ,anafeB aL“
,noitseuq a evah I“
,tuo tes dna dluoc eh tseb sa sknaht sih dias eH
,nwo sih lla dna lufituaeb
.ylpeed ni dehtaerb dna
”.thgin eht rof pu esolc dluoc I os emoh mih koot elcnu siH
,mih morf devomer gnol os sbmil esu ot gnitneirosid saw tI
.ydob sih otni dna pu dehsur dna
dah lesniT cinap lauxesib eht llA
,dnuorg eht no talf saw
.taht ot yas ot tahw wonk ton did anafeB aL
:ciler a saw noitats ehT
”.si ti woh wonk uoy
,ydob elttirb sih deggeb eh ”,esaelP“
”.ni emoc I nehw reduol yllausu s’tI“
.revo taht thguoht elgniJ
noitazilivic otni kcab yaw sti sedore ssenredliw erehw snigram eht ni erutaerc-flah eno
.was ehs tahw yb kcaba nekat saw ehs
”?gniknird uoy era tahW“
.gnihcaorb eb ot thguo eh tcejbus a saw siht erus t’nsaw eh fi sa
,hcamots dluoc I sgnos samtsirhC wef eht fo eno saw siht ,llitS
.yllanif dias elgniJ
.uoy htiw knird a teg ot evol d’I
”?flesruoy rof emit yna nekat uoy evah
.tenrag a ekil nihtiw peed thgil eht thguac eson dehsilop-htooms
,retnuoc eht revo denael dna
,desum xof flah eht
”.eno yppah a eb lliw ynahpipE yreve toN
.eot ot daeh morf reh derevoc taht wons eht ffo hsurb ot swap reh desu ehs sa dehctaw eH
kcab reh ta deppihw dniw eht
.sknaht oN“ ”?ekil uoy fi
tuoba woh ;yako s’tahT“
”?daetsni tnimreppep
.mih ot retnuoc eht ssorca repap eht edils dna gnitirw hsinif mih dehctaw lesniT
.psag citamard rehtona evag dna
.ti ot hcnuh thgils a dah kcab reh dna
.smra sih etacirtxe mih pleh ot
”?neht ,egnellahc eht taht sI“
,thgirb erew sthgil nrehtron eht tub ,yats ot detivni saw eh ,llef thgin sA
.woleb dnuorg eht ot deppird dna tuons sih fo htgnel eht delevart yeht sa seye sih fo srenroc eht kcirp sraet leef dluoc eH
,ti ees I yaw eht tuB
.retnirp eht morf tpiecer sih gnikat ,slegab fo gab eht pu dekcip dna
.demaeb flow eht dna
,regdab eht detcejretni
,redic fo noitacilppa suoiciduj a htiw ssenyrd taht xif ot desuap dna
”.ti ot ssenteews-
.noinapmoc ediserif eht devresbo
,nepo rood eht hsup ot redluohs rieht gnisu ,rood eht sdrawot sdrawkcab deklaw yehT
.erohs eht dehcaer ylefas eh dna
,evac sih fo egde eht dehcaer eh nehW
.nottub ffo eht tih yletaidemmi t’ndah I yhw saw hcihw
.pans a htiw tuo tpael tlob a dna
,tnemom a rof tsuj dna
,gniciton enoyna tuohtiw egduj detcele neeb yltnerappa dah noinapmoc ediserif eht
.peels ot emit dah syawla eh tub
.yldneirf dna eltneg saw eciov siH
.worb sih deworruf eH ”...lleW“
.gnorw ton er’uoY .oN“
.kcen gnol s’reyerF fo kcab eht no dednal dna
,sregdaB kooB eht fo ”,kcobnegeiZ“ yb
.seryt fo elbmur sseltneler eht dna ynotonom eht kaerb ot
.thguorb I yrots eht tuoba dnatsrednu t’nod I gnihtemos tsuj s’ereht
.rehtona eno ot dnuob ronoh er’uoy neht ,emoh ruoy ni tlas dna daerb setsat tseug a ecnO“
.pleh t’nseod ti ,esirprus dna
”rehtaeW eht ni egnahC A“ dnA
.retniw hsrah a lleterof yeht dna
tuons nailitper gnol s’reyerF
.kcab em gniggard tpek kcap ym tub
,mrof sih revo thgil eht dessap ehs nehW
seye sih detniuqs dna
.eulb-DEL dewolg dooh detsud-wons eht rednu seye reH
.em ot ti dednah neht
.lesniT ,wonk uoY“
”.ereh devil ohw sdneirf ym yllaicepsE
,nolat dehctertstuo sih tih sraet eht fo eno nehW
,mirt daerbregnig sti htiw egattoc elttil eht was eh nehT
taht gnihtemos gniwohs ecaf sih
,ytinummoc sih demrahc snoitcefnoc sih dna ronaemed teews siH
,deffuhc noillats eht
,nwotsamtsirhC fo seiradnuob eht tsap raf devil eH .dias yeht
”!ediserif tsrif ruoy ecnis uoy nees ev’I kniht t’nod I“
detcepxe neeb d’eh fi sa—
snezitic wollef sih hctaw ot elba gnieb fo wolg eht ni deksab lesniT ,nruter ni dna
”!mhM“ ”?yadot dedeen uoy gnihtyreve taht saW
”.edistuo og ot raeg muucav eht no tup ot dah I dna tibro ni erew eW“
.mih morf drac eht koot lesniT
rood eht ot tnew eh sa emoh ta gnileef fo esnes ddo na dah
”.smrots hcus ni gniylf ot desu si sniatnuom eseht fo nogard A
,remrahc eniuqe eht dias ”,lleW“
reed eht evoba hgih derewot
.deppalrevo yeht sa
.yendoR ta pu gnikool
.sredro rieht rof gnitiaw
”?kcab og ot detnaw reven ev’uoy dnA“
.mih ot revo yaw reh edam ehs sa roolf eht gnola swap reh delffuhs ehS
,wap a htiw kcab ti dessot yeht sa
.tsaef eht fo srevotfel eht ediseb ecalp ot
eh dna ,nwotsamtsirhC ni sesuoh eht ekil tsuj dekool tI
.ruf ym hguorht thgir elgnit a tnes ti
.yppah m‘I os ,enihcam osserpse ym htiw yalp ot esucxe na em evag uoy ,lleW“
.retnuoc eht otno derettalc dna sdnah sih fo tuo llef drac eht
”,mih dnif reven ll’uoY“
,tfig a sa ,edam d’eh selbuab ssalg nwolb-dnah fo tes a laever ot esac sih denepo flowsedart ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”,allerauqsaP oznecniV“ yb ”nwoT s’lesniT“ erew seirots detubirtnoC .2 fo 1 traP
.daor yrev taht nwod
,yadot ereh pu teiuq neeb s’tI
.detfihs reyerF ni gnihtemoS
,htiw reh detpurretni reyerF
.erahs ot sekac-ssom sih tuo thguorb elgniJ
”rotinaJ motnahP“ fo rohtua eht
—“ .sraluger sih fo eno ot redro gnol eht gnitaeper ,gab repap a ni seikooc fo sexob eht gnikcats saw eH
”ediR retniW tsaL enO“
”?deen fo ruoh ruoy ni elataN obbaB si erehW
.remotsuc tsal sih ot denrut dna
dnuorg eht morf wons eht hsurb ot yltnegilid dekrow dna
,letnam eht ta dezag eH ”.os ebyaM“
”.daor eht nwod selim noillim a eb rehtar d’uoy nehw neve ,yppah eb ot erusserp taht llA
.sreltna sih ni delgnat yllacigetarts sthgil yriaf htiw
,deffins tacyella citenrebyc eht
,knird ot gnimraw gnihtemos dah enoyreve litnu—
,noen ni detarutas metot etaroproc fo kcal eht dna ruoh eht neviG
”.gniog uoy peek dluohs siht ,lleW“
.daor eht no kcab teg ot ,gniog teg ot detnaw I
.enog eb lla ll’ti ,skeew elpuoc a ni ,lleW“
.txen og“ ,dias rekihhctih eht
tnelis saw thgin eht dna dehsinav meht fo tsal eht litnu
.doow dna ,gnildnik
”!taht naht rerettib ksa  t’ndluoc uoy“
.samtsirhC devresed yehT
”,mrywkooB irikeneN“ yb
.krow rof sepicer wen pu kniht rO
.doof eht rof daeh dna flowerew eht dnuora kcud ot ytinutroppo eht koot ehS
”.htnom edirp rof tnaem saw ti dias d’uoy fi ti thguob evah dluow I“
,ylird dias flowedart eht ”,nehw ecniS“
,dnelb ecips retniw a rehtegot dexim I“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,syadiloH yppaH
,mur derettub toh rehtona htiw puc sih dellifer noinapmoc ediserif eht nehw ylgninoitseuq pu decnalg rekihhctih ehT
.eert eht ot meht dda depleh
,meht denepo eh nehW
.efil ot enihcam eht thguorb flow ehT
.neht dna won eugra ew ,naem I
”—uoy erus ekam tsuJ
.lufesu eb ot evah t’nseod era uoy ohw tuB
.kcats a morf detfil gnieb etalp a draeh tsuj d’eH
.seirreb s’niatnuom eht no tsorf fo etsat eht devol rethguad sih yaw eht dna
.skooboidua rof noitarran gnizama ekam dluow thguoht lesniT taht rebmit htooms ,peed a dah tI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.emoc t’ndid tseuqer eht tub ,ksa ot mih rof detiaw elgniJ
.sregnif sih evom ot elba saw eh
”,knird txen eht regaw d’I“
.gniog ma I erehw ees ot elba eb ot deen I tub
”?taht si erehw dnA“
.evila llits saw eh taht deerga neve enoyreve toN
.ssenisub taht lla dna ’ylimaf rof emit a si samtsirhC
”.gnirpsffo ruoy ot dessap eb t’ndluow ti ezilaer t’ndid I tub
;emoh sih dedraug sretsnom-wons dias emoS
,fo draeh reve dah tlobelgniJ reednier tsedlo eht saw eh ,enola sreltna gnihcnarb sih no desaB
tuanortsa eht nehw
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daer
”,dneirf ym ,ytilatipsoh tneicnA“
.niaga deddon reednier redlo ehT
.denimreted saw eh tub
.hpmh tfos a evag dna
.pot no dnabtah eht ni ylloh fo girps a htiw tah pot a decnalab neht dna ,sgniw cinocard gnilaever
”?emoh morf raf os reednier gnuoy a sgnirb tahw“
”?ti od llits uoy dluow ,oS“
.nos dlo-raey-owt s’reednier eht fo eman eht saw
.sexob etihw llams otni seikooc gnikcap
,sdnah htiw stnediser rof tliub neeb ylsuoivbo dah ecalp eht
erew ’ymrots‘ dna ’krad‘ tub—
.naoM hanniS ssiM .eniF“ .reduol elttil a hgual tub pleh t’ndluoc lesniT
,drac ruoF warD dliW eht nwod gniworht fi sa decnuonna flowsedart eht ”,era uoy erehT“
.enigne ym ffo tuhs I dna
.mih ot kcab ti gnidnah
.taht wenk yeht erus saw lesniT tub
”.llet draeh ev’I os ro“ ,deggurhs flowerew eht ”,seitrap samtsirhc ta semag yalp elpoeP“ ”?tsetnoc a ti si“
roolf evac eht morf pu
.stfig eht yrrac enola tel ,mrots siht ni ylf ot elba eb t’ndluow eH
,lleW“ ”.flesym syenruoj rieht gnirahs m’I ,yaw a nI
yoj rof depmuj ehS
,pot parts ittehgaps etihw a
.eltnam eht fo renroc eht yb gnidnats tsuj ro ,htraeh eht fo tnorf ni gur eht no
.mih ta nwod dekool yendoR
,maets htiw gnillif saw nibac elttil ehT
syaw etarapes rieht detfird yehT
,sehtolc krow sih revo tsiaw sih dnuora deit norpa neerg a dah eH
’rettiB‘ .teews tub gnihtyna thguorb ydobon taht“
.tonnac I tub ,dluoc I fi dluoW“
.eciov rehtona emac
.tfig etunim-tsal a rof hcraes etarepsed a dna ,sdik tuo-desserts ,seilimaf deirraH
– spmup sag tneicna owt dna
”.srexim eht fo dnuos eht ekil t’nseod eH
gnivaw ,yawrood eht ni
,snoitaroced wef a denethgiarts
.sgum dehctamsim eht fo eno rof dehcaer god elbanoinapmoc eht
,lleW .yrots ruoy tuoba toN“
—ot elbaliava saw ijaR erus gnikam htiw dna ,ynniC htiw
.tisiv ym rof nosaer eht desseug tsomla evah uoy rof ,oot tramS .reyerF ,tsoh suoicarg a era uoY“ ”.uoy
,rekihhctiH flowereW eht denialpxe
,dekcap saw eludehcs sih ,eruS
.sneergreve fo evorg a ni deltsen
.gnihtoos saw eciov siH ”.seY“
,yawrood llah eht hguorht ni dekcud noillats emosdnah A
”?dnabsuh eht s’woH“
ediserif deyats ria eht dna dnuos on edam dah rood tnorf eht hguoht
gab eht fo pot eht pu dedlof lesniT
:reh pots ot tpmetta on edam rekihhctih ehT
”ygolohtnA samtsirhC noitciF hsalF yrruF A !syadilwoH yppaH“
.yako syawla saw ti tuB
”.ni gnidaeh wef a n’erom raeh dluoc I ycnaf I tub ,pu wohs lla ew llit yas ot draH“ .mraw-
”.renroc eht dnuora tsuj si gnirps dna
,elbag yreve no sthgil fo sgnirts ehT
.sesac emos ni segareveb gnitarogivni wef a htiw dna rethgual htiw
”?yaw eht yb ,leuf ynA“
,yrekab eht edisnI
?uoy ot deneppah tahW …reyerF ,hO“
”.yenruoj gnol a dah ev’uoY“
.dias elgniJ ”,yrroS“
.tekcaj mined a dna
wons eht otni ydob sih fo tser eht llup ot mih dewolla smra siH
.reednier eht no tsol ton erew meht dniheb liat gnihsiws eht dna
.daeh sih detlit elgniJ
.em eugirtni did taht woN
.kcits wolG .sag pmawS“
…’reehc doog fo eb‘ ot em llet derad yeht fi dnA
— esruoc fo – reh wenk eH
.yaw nwo ruoy nosaes eht kraM
,etals dekcarc fo foor a ,srebmit dekoorc htiw esuoh nedoow a
…eb tsuj nac tI .egatnavda na eb ot evah t’nseod tI
,seigolohtna lareves fo rotide sulp
.dlo syad owt tuoba tlef elgniJ ylnedduS .nees enola tel
.tnemom a rof desuap I
”.elcarim samtsirhc a si“
.yltfos delkcuhc lesniT
,yrekab eht htiw elttes ot deen dluow eh sgniht ynam os erew ereht tuB
,snaej ynniks thgit fo riap a erow ,roverT ,xof ehT
,hcuoc eht no nekat erew secalp
,denesool ,dehcterts selcsuM
.roirp sraey eerht
,erif eht morf thgil eht htiw gnilgnim ,sllaw eht revo gniremmihs arorua s’taoc sih dehctaw tlobelgniJ
.rood eht tuhs god ehT .niaga ecno
,tib a elzzum sih detfil eH
,lufecaep fo dnik saw tI .daor larur
.eno yb eno ni slegab eht tup ot nageb dna
,noitatiga htiw yliratnulovni dehctiwt sreksihw reH
.emit lufsserts a eb nac tI“
.t’ndah uoy fi thgir meht devres evah dluow ti kniht I—esuaceB
...rekab lufsseccus a dna rehtaf elgnis a gnieb neewteb tuB
.rehto eht fo ruovalf eht tuo gnignirb hcae
.meht ot yako ti edam taht neht dna ,lufesu gnihtemos otni ti denrut yehT
,decneirepxe reve
.ti fo kniht ot emoc
”,neht ,stseug rehto eht rof tlas dna daerb emos evaS“
,lwo regnessem s’atnaS ,gniwtsorF yb edam pam dlo na dewollof eH
”.tsael ta sruoh eerht ro owT .haeY“
,drawrof tneb saw ydob reH
redro s’drehpehS eht htiw gab eht gnillif dehsinif lesniT
,dias dna daeh reh koohs anafeB aL
.wons nellaf ylhserf ekil dnim sih ni gnilip tpek seiromem ehT
,elbapacseni saw ti ,rebmeceD ni won dna
– troffe fo tol a htiw – dna
.uoy pots t’now I ,mrots eht morf retlehs kees ot hsiw uoy fi ,revewoH
”tsaeF yadiloH eht retfA gniteeM ediseriF“ saw sihT    ”.thguorb
.no llits saw oidar ehT
.stressed sih fo eno otni etib
”?uoy llac yeht od seman tahW“
…tsuj yehT“ .deilper I
.tiftuo rieht fo tser eht dna ecaf rieht ot derutseg xof ehT
.etalocohc toh fo slwob owt pu gnippihw ylksirb elbuort on dah hploduR
.sey yas ot detnaw eH
.pu emit emos raelc ot gnilliw eb d’uoy fI
”.esoppus I ,retniw stius“
.eniw toh sih revo maets otni deffup sdrow s’xof desserd-llew eht
,emit driht eht rof ,niaga tnemetats eht gniraeH
.delims hploduR taht ylregae os ti dias elgniJ ”.os epoh I“
,wonk uoy ,feiler a tsomla saw tI …tub ,semitemos
.tuo denniht dah sthgil yriaf eht ,ereh tuo tsael tA
.evoba srats eht sa thgirb sa erew
.gninrub ecaf sih tlef eh dna ,ediw erew seye sih
,deunitnoc flowsedart eht
,sthgil eht nwod denrut eH
”.uoy htiw gnihtemos od ot evol d’I tuB
.sexob eht otni meht tup eh sa seikooc eht fo hcae fo llems eht ta dehctiwt eson s’lesniT
.rehtona sdnatsrednu
,raew retniw yldrah saw tI
,mur derettub toh rof flowerew eht
.retnuoc eht ssorca gab eht dils lesniT
.noitatiseh tuohtiw derewsna eh ”,sey hO“
.evom ot ydob sih dedeen eh
,rettal eht rof maerc hsiri fo hcuot a htiw
er’ew woh s’taht“
.sepols ydniw gnitagivan dna stfird hguorht gnigdurt ,tuo tes dna
”.knat eht ni hguone tog ev’I kniht I ,haN“
”.stnuoc taht fI“ ,xof-flah desserd-llew eht dias ”…wonk t’nod I“
.daeh sih koohs hploduR
.deddon dna pu dekool lesniT
,eltsac eht ni mih dnif d’eh thguoht elgniJ ,tsrif tA
.syenruoj rieht tuoba gniraeh ,slamina fo sgniog dna sgnimoc eht gnihctaw
”,gnihtyna ta gnitepmoc eb d’ew wenk su fo enon gniredisnoc hcihW“
?ti od llits uoy dluow ,revo ti od dluoc uoy fI
”,srevotfel fo ytnelp s’ereht ,lleW“
,won sthgil rewef erew erehT
”?ecalp tsrif eht ni tisiv yhw ,egami ruo evah neve t’nod ew fi“
,emases eerht ,gge eerhT“
.liat dna sgniw sih egrembus dna
.delims noinapmoC ediseriF eht
.tpecca ot etalp sih nwod tes ot dah rekihhctiH flowereW eht hcihw ,ecarbme na dereffo noinapmoC ediseriF eht
gniteeM ediseriF“   ,yojne esaelP
.degdelwonkca remrahc eniuqe eht
.thguoht I ,muidet eht kaerb ot yaw a eb dluoc tI
”.ylimaf gniees tsuJ .laiceps erehwoN“
”,llew sa yam I sseug I“
.elpmis os ton si tI“
”.tuo seog thgil ruoy nehw era sdneirf laer ruoy ohw tuo dnif uoY“
,tsael ta doohrobhgien siht ni ,sesuoh ynam toN
,mih fo evael reh koot ehs ,oS
,gnihtyna naht eroM
,mih htiw erew sedit eht dna kcul tub ,tseb ta ydaetsnu saw tfar tfihsekam siH
,deddon I ”?ti ekil uoy oD“
.thgis eht ta epaga saw htuom s’anafeB aL
.thgis ni kcurt aloc a ton dna ,dloc ,naelc
?rewsna ruoy evig uoy nehw em ta kool ton uoy od yhW“ ”.ton lliw I ,oN“
lesniT ta kool tsal eno koot eH ”.thgiN“
,elzzum sih derevoc dna knoh suovren a tuo tel lesniT
?hctiw ,ta gnirats uoy era tahW“
,eton ykcits a no rebmun a delbbircs ,nep a koot eH
.dluoc eh sa ylkciuq dna ylpmis sa hturt eht dias tsuj eh won tub ,snoitasrevnoc fo snezod desraeher dah elgniJ ,yaw eht gnola llA
”.gnidaeh m’I erehw tuoba laiceps gnihton s’ereht
.daetsni pu ekops regdab eht ”,hguoht
.yats em gnikam saw gnihtemos tuB
”!egnaro etalocohc a sa teews saw gnidne taht tuB“
”.uoy ot tcepsersid on tnaem I“
,sgniw evissam sih dexelf eH
,tsaf etiuq si moorb yM
,erofeb neeb reve d’yeht naht regnorts
”?roverT ,gnihtyna tegrof I diD
,edis rehto eht no gnidnats sremotsuc owt erew erehT
hguohT .otni elttes ot roolf eht no snoihsuc kciht dna
,reehc dna ,htmraw dellips ti morf dna
.rac gnissap ddo eht dna thgil-esuoh lanoisacco eht morf edisa
.remrahC eniuqE eht
ssim I sgniht era erehT“
.tsur dna tniap der htiw dedaf
elbahsiugnitsidni ylfeirb emaceb sgniteerg laudividnI
”.tegrof …tsuj I sseug I .tol a od I
”.doof eht rof thgiarts tnew uoy desirprus eb t’ndluohs I“
.dnah sih evom dluoc eh dna ,pord rehtonA
.delkcuhc hploduR
”?etad a no em gniksa uoy erA“
”.em ton ,degnahc taht rehtaew eht saw tI
.deniatniam xof eht
skcits fo edam moorb a tuo thguorb ehS
.mih ot enituor os emoceb tsuj dah sgniht esoht llA …dnA
.deddon drehpehS ehT ”?slegaB“
.swalc ym ni gniggid
.kcab gninrut on saw ereht ,tlobelgniJ rof tuB
.delims neht dna tnemom a mih ta nwod dezag hploduR
.waht s’emitgnirpS ni eci eht hguorht gnikaerb retaw eht ekil
,eert samtsirhc fo ylno thgil eht yb nehT
”?esle gnihtyna od uoy oD
retal tnemom a ylnO
,reffo eht ta kcohs sih ni tuB
”.meht htiw eb dna eid tonnac I wonk uoy nehT“ .delworg reyerF
.daeh sih fo pot no pu dekrep srae sih dna ,deddon yendoR
.tseb eht rof s’tI .hguoht thginot toN .si tI .haeY“
.eson denekrad sih gnitacidni
”.riaffa elohw eht fo ytinirahccas eht OT NOITISOPPO NI dna TUOBA rettib tub ,rettib tsuj ton“
,puc eht em dednah flow eht nehw dnA
”.tat tsilaicremmoc eht tuohtiw od
,suorehcaert yllaicepse saw trap tsal ehT
’,tnelis’—thgin eht ot sevitcejda rehto ylppa thgim esruoc fo emoS
”?esaelp ,siht htiw dnah a teg I dluoc ,hU“
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb daer
.tcepsersid yna naem t’nod I“
.ereh drah os krow uoY“
,raey gnimoc eht rof sehsiw dna
,tacyella eht dehgual ”,sdnuos tahT“ ”-os ,won EREH
stuons rieht no yoj reehs eht dna devol erew yeht wohs ot stfig meht nevig dah eH
.hctiw ,srovaf rof
”?naem uoy od tahW“
”?redisnocer ton uoy lliW
.thginot reh morf tisiv a detcepxe t’ndah tub
.ylthgirb derewsna tuanortsa eht ”,thgirla gnioD“
.doof doog fo ecnadnuba taerg a fo llems eht dna
”!teews saw taht ,lleW“
.mih ot nekops reve dah yendoR tsom eht saw sihT
.yaw ym no eb dna ,yap ,eeffoc a barG .thgiR
,rood nehctik eht ta ni retaews dedooh suonimulov a ni tacyella na tel rekihhctih ehT ”,evah dluoc uoY“
tac citenrebyc eht dna regdab ylrehtaf eht rof aococ ,tuanortsa eht dna flowsedart eht rof redic toh—
,samtsirhC erofeb keew eht saw tI
,elttek gnilbrub yltfos a dna erif gnilkcarc a htiw htraeh enots a
.seirots yadiloh erom raeh ot lla fo tsom tub
”.taht ekil gnihtemos ,wonk uoy ,rO
.lwob sih otni derats elgniJ
.deddon tacyella citenrebyc eht ”,hguoht teews nmad ytterp llits saw tI“
”.tsrif og ot sah ydobemos sseug“
.tnimreppep fo tnecs naelc prahs eht dna ,eeffoc gnitsaor hcir
,erofeb lla ti draeh ev’uoY
”,dne eht ta teews sdrawot nrut eht dnA“
.derekcilf eson sih dna ,dehcnilf hploduR
”.taht tuoba dellirht oot dnuos t’nod uoY“
tsehc rieht ot wap rieht desserp neeuq gard ehT
.hsulb a ot denethgirb dna delppir skeehc s’elgniJ ni sthgil ehT
”.si taht revetahw ,lybonrehC .gulp krapS
.nrecnoc saw sseug ylno dluoc lesniT
”.eeffoc ni ecips htiw noissesbo eht dootsrednu reveN
.secalperif lanoitcnuf dah llits
,dehgis flowsedart derevuenamtuo ehT
”.ih dias I slrig eht lleT“
- ekil uoy nosaes eht tuoba gnihtemos s’ereht ebyaM
.reyerF ecaf ot dnuora denrut ylwols neht
– hcihw ruf yerg yffurcs htiw ,seitrof ro seitriht sih ni saw eH
.gnikniht llits ,retsiger eht ot devom neht dna
tnimreppep fo tnecs dloc gniregnil eht dna ,daerbregnig eht ,eldoodrekcins eht morf lemarac ehT
”!evas ot ynahpipE na tog ev’eW
,rebotcO ecnis em no gnitarg neeb dah nosaes deruoloc-ydnac ,ylkcis ehT
.dexim lla seikooc thgileD retniW sih morf
,seye rieht ni feihcsim fo remmilg ehT
.ruovalf eeffoc wen a neve ro ,ebyam gnos a
,niur otni gnilbmurc dna denodnaba gnol saw ti was eh ,resolc tog eh sa tub
,eceip evitaroballoc a fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT
”,uoy wohs dluoc …I“
.maets gnissih eht revo tuo dellac eh
”.snaem lla yb ,seY“ ”.egral dnA .kcalB
?ssenippah rieht nerdlihc esoht yned ot eh saw ohW
.thgin ymrots a ron krad a rehtien saw tI  .2 fo 1 traP
.retaw fo loop tseraelc eht naht retteb saw
,tuo tellaw sih koot dna
.yrekab eht fo tuo deklaw ylwols dna
,yticirtcele htiw delkcarc sdub-reltna siH .mih edisni arorua na deirrac eh fi sa ,liat ot srae morf
”.no gninihs peek ,sthgil samtsirhC ,hO
draobedis eht ta flesmih deisub noinapmoc ediserif ehT
”.enog eb dna og nehT“
.yllufthguoht deddon hploduR
,em rof gnitiaw erew selbuort yM .ylno fI
”.emit ruoy ekaT .yako s’tI“
.edisni thgil a was I ,dewols dna dellangis I sa tuB
.delkcuhc eH ”.niS ,seY“
.stnerruc ria elbatciderpnu emos ot eud eolf eci na no edir a gnihctac devlovni ti sa
.yks eht sa raelc sa erew sklawedis dna steerts eht
tsuj dluoc I .gnihserfer s’tI
,ylesolc mih dehctaw yendoR
;retnuoc eht ta gnikool ,ti dennacs dna drac eht pu dekcip ylkciuq eh ,deretsulF
snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT morf elbaliava
,llaH retraC eeneR
”?uoy htiw yako taht sI“
.taorht ruoy ni kcuts ydnac nottoc ekil ,gnitacoffus
.nrut ni kcab emac hcae tub
.oot enif s’taht ,ton fi dnA
,kcartaoc eht no taoctaerg dna fracs sih gnuh xof desserd-llew yrev a
.fooh tnorf a htiw yltneg dekconk dna
dna gnipeews reh dehsinif anafeB aL
nehw dnA .emoc ot sraey eht ni revocsid ot seiretsym dna srednow htiw
eciov gnilkcarc a ni ekops reyerF
”.tey ti lortnoc yllaer t’nac I“
.reyerF nihtiw derrits lufrednow gnihtemos
.tohs a htrow saw ti ebyam …ebyaM
”?detrats teg ew llahS“
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT
.sdrow sih revo elbmuts reednier eht dehctaw eh sa pu dekriuq spil sih
.yaw emas eht tlef yeht ylno fI
.enihcam eeffoc nailatI reporp a htiw rab a saw edis eno ot ffO
.sraey ni srotisiv thguos ton d’eH
,tekcaj ymra dehctap dna derettab a meht ot txen gnuh
.rebmun enildnal a s’taht seY“
.evac eht fo ecnartne eht edistuo kcab
.rac ym ot denruter dna ,flow eht ot eybdoog dias I
slleweraf lufetarg no
,llaw eht pu uoy gnivird s’ylimaf ruoy ro ,tahc a ycnaf uoy emit yna tuB
,thguoht reh hsinif dluoc ehs erofeB ”—
.allerauqsaP oznecniV yb detide dna
,eno evah ot hguone ykcul esoht rof tuB
”oG oT eeffoC tnimreppeP“
”,llaH retraC eeneR“ yb