taht dna noitanicullah a lla s’ti taht flesmih llet ot seirt eh
.eno rehtona t’nsaw ereht ,ton ro
denodnaba dna dloc
.ti htrow eb lliw lla ta mih gniees esoppus I tuB
railimaf si roloc ehT
.eulb etals ro yerg laocrahc saw taoc sih rehtehw
.lanoitcif yleritne eb ot elbissopmi oot dednuos taht dnik eht
erif fo dnik thgir eht eb ot erif a rof naem llits dluoc uoy taht depoh eh
,thgink etal-oot yna ro ,ssertnahcne eht fi dnA .eerf saw ehS
enod dah ehs taht lla tnes ehs
laer saw ti rehtehW .teksab siht ni saw gge tsal siH
.mih ta kcab thgir gnirats erugif tahT
.xof revliS .revird rac ecaR
mrof redlo neve na ni ro
thgil sa latrommi dna tfiws sa
,ylregae gnimmuh snug ,kcolria eht dehcaerb
,mih eb lliw ees ll'I thgil tsrif eht
,gnorw mih devorp ev’I ,lleW
.mih ta deknilb tuanortsa ehT
.mrah morf efas ,sdioretsa eht fo stniop eht neewteb ylsseltroffe gnikirtS
,daerht fo roloc yreve dna
?yawyna ,ereh pu dniw uoy did woh …ekil“
,++C fo
erew seirots detubirtnoC
.gnilcric spihs ymenE
tuohtiw dlrow eht ni
.god eht deunitnoc
.eman tep taht setah eh wonk I hguoht neve
,yrotsih reh htiw nageb ehS
,sey dna ,edis ot edis morf d’kcarc retuor eht
.leirA noitalletsnoc eht fo tuo
:nageb noillats eht sa
,atadatem fo satsiv gnissentiw
.emit tsal eno xaroht ym gnivaS
,erif eht dehcaorppa eh sa decnuonna eh
.thgirla saw hcihw
.noillats eht dehsinif
.ecnatsissa rof daelp ,erehwemos daerht emos ,aidem laicos emos
.flesym ereht neeb ev’I
,kael tnalooc emos saw ereht ebyaM
.dia reh ot emoc dluow tolecnaL eb-dluow gnihsad emos
,”tleB repiuK retuO eht ni gniteeM ediseriF“ saw sihT
,ekaw txen I nehw
.deggurhs god eht
,ediserif eht fo tcaf eht tsuj s’erehT“ ”.maxe …on
,oot paeh a ni ecar eht fo tuo erew srac eht flaH .krad laeR
,yrots eht no desucof dna
.sreirrab etercnoc eht otni gnikcams ,tiucric eht ffo sneerac dna
.gnihtyna was ydoboN
.yawa raf yrev gnihtemos ot resolc gnitteg m’I dna
.gnirussaer t’nerew yehT
,erif eht drawot drawrof pets deticxe na koot god ehT
”ratS gnidiuG yM er’uoY“
,sretirw dna srevol ,srethgif dna sredaer roF“ ”.su
”.ti ediseb seirots derahs uoY
,epacse tuoba yrots a kcip d’uoy taht“
.eb ot esohc ehs ohw reh ekamer ot esoht fo seceip enodnu dah taht
,evoba spihs ymene eht fo egdelwonk eht dna
”.kcab gniog on s’ereht ,dnatsrednu t’nod uoy dlrow a ni toof tes uoy ecno‘
ekil sgniht dah taht stenalp rof tnaem ,raeg gnipmac pu denrut dloh ylppus eht ni gnigammur emoS
,mrots temoc eht fo edis siht no ,krad saw tI
,ecalp emas eht etiuq ni rac eht tog ton s’eh
”,yrots taht ot larom a s’ereht fi wonk t’nod I“
,trihs dna snaej gnikool elbatrofmoC
,rohtua eht yb daer
.sdrow cigam on ,lautir on ,dedeen uoy ecived on saw ereht taht
,dessap yeht sa semalf eht dennaf sgniw sih hguone tsaf ,dnuora denrut tuanortsa eht nehw tuB
.leehw eht skrej dna sekarb eht no smalS
,dias elosnoc eht ,elcyc dleihs rep stcapmi 61 fo egareva nA
,flesreh ot esu tsethgils eht ton fo erew taht
,yek a fo ekorts lanif eht htiw dnA .eman reh
,latipsoh ni pu sekaw eh nehW
”tleB repiuK retuO eht ni
.003 ,004 ,renroc eht ot sertem 005 ,wonk’Y .sngis rekram eseht rof gnihctaw s’eh
,ereh fo tuo noinapmoc derujni sih gnitteg fo
gnivom pihs eht leef nac I
,niaga kcen sih fo kcab eht no nwod erob ytissecen
.adirolF ni nwod ecar rac ecnarudne emit giB
,neppah meht ekam ot woh wenk eh taht
,neht tuB  ?laer saw siht fo enon dna ,gnitanicullah saw eh
kcart eht fo edis eht no tolip rethgif 2 raW dlroW a fo erugif deifibmoz eht nees s’eh taht nac eh enoyreve sllet eh
,enoemos s’ereht sa gnol sA“
.tnereffid leef ot
.doog taht ees t’nac nialp tsuj uoy os ereht tuo slavitsef gib ,ekil ton s’ereht dna
xaw dna plup doow dedurtxe—
,emeht eht fo noitareti siht no sehcuot lanosrep nwo reh tup dah
,delbmert eannetna yffulf s’tuanortsa ehT
,sdioretsa fo snrettap gnitfihs eht hguorht pihs nwo ym revuenam ot tseb ym deirt I
.niaga reve rac ecar a ni toof tas reven eH
.ereht ton saw ehS
.uoy tops t’ndid yeht epoh dna
.od stsitra lla sa
noitisop otni sedils pihs ym sA
sreyalp teppup-wodahs fo ynapmoc a
,ereht tuo gnihtemos s’ereht taht yas ot stip eht oidar ot seirt eH
,hcum taht gnitanimulli ton er’yeht os ,tsenoh er’ew fi
,ddo saw ti dnA
,emit siht ,neht tuB
.dnah s’ylferif suoicsnocnu eht ezeeuqs ot mih dniheb dehcaer htom ehT ”?og
.taes tolip eht morf delkcubnu ylluferac tuanortsa ehT
mool a nevig neeb evah dluow ehs ,lanigiro eht nI
.niaga reh hcuot reve dluoc
,noillats eht dias ”,ynnuF“
.deraef ehs seirots tsohg eht lla
.thgil otni ssam s’pihs sih trevnoc mih stel taht evird elcitrap emas eht evah t’nod I
.ti did I dalg m’I ,os nevE
.sih ekil tleb dioretsa eht hguorht piz ot dengised t’nsi pihs yM
”!haey hO“ ”.ti gnidnif
,swodniw eht morf llef lla sniatruc ehT .eerF
”tsaP eht fo stsohG“
,gniog saw I erehw fo esnes retteb a rof srosnes s’pihs eht ot annetna ym decnys neve I .gnitfird dna dehsams pu dne ot nrut gnorw eno saw koot ti lla tub
rorrim a evah ot tnaem si
,dlrow edistuo eht dloheb ot hcihw htiw
tuo dekconk steg eH
,em rof gniklat ytinav eb yam tI
.ssik tsrif reh fo thgin eht neeb dah rehtaew eht tahW
,kcab egassem a dnes ot em ta gnimaercs s’eH
.mih tfel yrots eht sa htom eht ta yletilop deddon noillats dna god ehT  .ecin eb
ni demihc ,tuoba saw noitasrevnoc eht tahw dootsrednu eh ecno niaga reppihc won ,god eht
.rehte eht otni deraeppasid ...tsuj eH
.liat sih deggaw dna ,htom eht ot denrut ,dehcterts god eht ”,lleW“
noitanimreted eht dna
.gninraw a depeeb elosnoc ehT -esuaceb
ro lluh degamad ym eruces ot em rof gninraw rehtonA
,sdnah citehtsorp yletacirtni htiw eannetna sih hsurb ot
s’ti ebyam ,si ereht fI“
.sediserif ta gnineppah sgniht tuoba selaT
dnuora ti sekam tub
.dnekeew siht semit derdnuh a siht enod s’eh
,deifsitas dekool noillats ehT
,dleifria 2 raW dlroW a no tliub saw ecalp sihT
,lluh eht no dednuos dah spetstoof on
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.deliaf rewop nehw mraw gnipeek ro gnikooc rof—
,yranib fo shtap nwod gninnur saw ehS
ytrap gnidraob eht dna
,eb ot tnaem si draob ertem 002 eht erehw ,niaga ecno dnA
yrots sih saw sihT
.roolf daehklub eht no
lidneraE ot meht htiw edir a dehctih d’ohw flow ehT
,denepo t’ndah skcolria ehT .eciov a dias
.citats si gnitteg s’eh lla tub
”…yna evah I kniht t’nod I
.llits deniamer ria gnilats ylwols eht dna
ot gniog yllautca era ohw sklof eht dniheb spal 5 tuoba gninnur er’yeht
.seirots reh etorw ehs
.reh tisiv ot emac enoN .eid dluow ehs
,hcaeb a no lamron dekool ev’dluow eH
.pal txen eht dnuora no seirrac os ,sgniht gniees tsuj s’eh taht dna
.tuo kcuf eht skaerf ykciR
.gnitouq erew eh fi sa ,noillats eht deticer
.esruc s’ssertnahcne eht yb dehsubma neeb dah ehs woh dna erehW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ehcatsum delruc ,riah gniwolf gnol ,enodnu snottub pot
,edoc evaew tub od dluoc ehs gnihton saw ereht fI .krow ot tes ehs
”.neppah dluow tahw ro gniod erew yeht saw ti tahw wonk t’ndluoc yeht fi neve etarepsed gnihtemos gniyrt enoemos dna
,saw ehs ohw reh edam dah taht seirots eht llA
.noinapmoc sih morf naom suoicsnocnu deniap rehtonA
”.seirots eht dna ,snoinapmoc eht
,gniht dlo siht evah yehT
,llew ,su sekam tahw s’tahT“
”?ti leef uoy t’naC“ .dennirg god ehT
mih no sdne spaws tsuj rac eht ,esruoc fO
,eciov sih dnuof yllanif htom eht ”…I“
.ekil eht dna ,LMTH ,avaJ
.nees s’eh tahw tuoba eramthgin suoedih gnikcuf tsom eht gnivah strats dna
.ssensuoicsnocnu decudni-rellikniap ni neve
.yug eht fo erugif lluf eht sees eh ,emit siht tuB
dicul peek ot tluciffiD
.smetsys troppus efil gniliaf ym ot
eceip evitaroballoc a si yrots s’yadoT dna
,rood eht hguorht derednaw god A ”!dliW“
.tenretni eht otni tuo
”.ediseb seirots llet ot erif a gnithgil
”,dlot era seirots erehw detinu ereh lla era
raey a ynam neeb dah tI
.seirujni sih kcehc ot
.sgnidnal hsarc ta doog nettog dah eh taht detah htom ehT
.hcum os hguorht tup neeb sah ydob ym nehw
.wonk I dna eh ylno edoc A
.ereht wodahs a s’ereht daetsnI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,s’08 eht morf sgniht yggof dlo er’yeht
,yrots a llet ot desoppus saw I wonk t’ndid I“
,tiusecaps a tuohtiw osla
tpek dna ,detnioppa ylhcir ,elbatrofmoc—
.ytilanosrep reh etorw ehs txeN
,4991 nI
…krow t’ndid siht fi emit ssel htiw meht evaeL
.tnaem taht revetahW
,reh nopu emoc dluow esruc eht
,segnuol noitats latibro dna srab tropecaps ni raeh uoy dnik eht
tuanortsa eht sa oS
dluow tahT .em ta nwod gninworf
.mih eveileb lliw ydobon esruoc fo dna
,esruoc fo ,cissalc dlo na saw esruc ehT .srats eht ro
,ecnatsid eht ni tniaf
.tnits lanif eht rof rac eht otni tup si ykciR
.ydob reh ni regnol on saw ehs tuB
,htom eht ta decnalg eh
,depoh ro ,detcepxe d’eH
,elbac citpo rebif a hguorht
.ssensselthgiew dna niap fo sevaw eht neewteb tniopnip ot drah s’tI
.od ot evah dluow
.ereht doots erugif siht s’ereht
,elohtrop a tuo ylregae dereep
,won rof efas tnaem taht dna
rebmahc reh evael ton dluoc ehs taht
secnacifingis citsym fo lluf yrtsepat a evaew ylsseldne ot hcihw htiw
selbatsubmoc mret gnol fo egakcap a dedulcni tI
.niaga eciov sih fo zzub tnasaelp eht raeh ot evig t’ndluow I tahW
,002 rof skool eh sA
”?pihsecaps a siht si ,haoW“ ”?yeht t’nod
,relevart wollef ruoy
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,nwod erew yeht dna ,dah eh tuB
,daeh sih detlit htom ehT
.roolf eht ssorca dehsup riahc a fo dnuos eht ta deltsirb ruf reh yaw ehT
,yks eht ssorc' tlob a ekiL  ”…yrt ll’I“
.noitcennoc tenretni na dah lrig eht
…tsuj nac ew …nac I naem uoY“
.sdrawretfa ykciR ot deneppah tahw nwod etorw ydoboN
,ssertnahcne dekciw eht sa snoitidart emas eht ni hguone desrev saw ehs tuB
.kcart eht no thgiarts tsegnol eht si hcihw
,flesmih ot htom eht thguoht ,ebyaM
.ti dnif t’nseod eh
,denrutnu nosirp reh fo enots yna evael ton dluow taht dnim fo dnik ehT
.sgnos etirovaf reH .sekilsid reh ,sekil reH .luos reH
ffo gnieb troppus efil tsael tA
spahreP .srulb noisiv yM
,og ot sruoh 2 tuoba htiW
”,cissalc dlo na no tsiwt a saw ti taht dekil tsuj I ,naem I“
kniht thgim uoy ,woN
.eannetna yrehtaef ,gnireviuq desiar
,eucser rof llac naht rehtar oS
gnihton reh evael dna
.etarepsed gnihtemos yrt ot emiT .gnitiaw on ,oN
.noisiv larehpirep ym ni ffo dna no sknilb
.sraef tsrow sih demrifnoc elosnoc eht morf peeb rehtona tuB
.gnilf a sa pihsnoitaler ruo evael t’ndluoc I
.taert gniticxe na erew taht fi sa
,ecnerehocni fo tniop eht ot tsomla knurd neeb d’eh hguoht ,detsisni dah
.dneB tesnuS dellac nipriah ypmub repus ,gib siht sdrawot yawnur a nwod evird yllaretil uoY
,ylbatrofmoc tis ot hguone llat neeb ev’dluow esle ydobon erehw
.daehrevo serutangis enigne ymenE
.kcab em gnillup tpek thgil siH
,taht dehsinif dah ehs nehW
.seitilibissop hguorht thguoht eh sa dereviuq sgniw s’tuanortsa ehT
,gnihtemos tuoba thgir nevorp neeb d’eh fi sa
,ereh fo tuo gnitteg ta ecnahc ylno sih etsaw dna—
,ebyam ,pleh emos deen tsuj uoY .t’nseod ohw nosrep a sa gniht hcus oN
,sretaw eht no noom eht ro
.dik ,erif eht til uoY“
,noillats eht dias ”,yrrow t’noD“
retupmoc a dah ehs ereh tub
),derettam taht fi sa( ecaf ylevol a dah ehs ,htaed ni ,rehtehw ees ot yb emoc ot deneppah
emit hguone nevig ylerus dna
gnieb hcihw fo ycnetop ehT
,thgin ta kcolc’o 01 tuoba s’ti oS
,part eht gnirps ylno dluow moor eht morf eucser taht desseug dna
.dloh ograc degamad eht morf gnigreme ton tub ,cincip a ro
”,emit dnoces ym ylno si
.ti od ot reh nekat dah ti ,etad ot ,gnol woh dna
,thgil esuffid eht ni ,llet ot drah saw tI
,eseht fo daetsni ,lleW .llaw eht no
.no tel dluoc eh naht erom derac eh wonk I
,22 tuoba saw eh nehw
,ylevitpecrep ,yldetniop ,ecaf gnol sih nwod dekool eH
,murof emos no tuo hcaer ot reh rof
,emit tsal eht rof ffo derewop ti sa rotinom eht no enohs nus eht fo thgil eht
.nampahC-sebroF ykciR dellac yug a tuoba yrots a daer I
snoitubirtnoc htiw
,larenuf a evah tsum eno fi ,taht desoppus ehs elihw dnA .larenuf
.nemodba ym ni ylbatrofmocnu gnihsols flah rehto eht dna g orez ni gnitaolf era sdiulf ym flaH
,snoisrev lanigiro eht nI
”,erehpsomta na“ dna ”,efil“
,floWcaM boR si sihT
”?ereh tog uoy revewoH
.sruoh 21 gnirbeS eht ta edir siht flesmih tog d’eh
.tuokaerb eht evivrus ot tub
.em did taht doog eht lla rof
.seye sih fo setihw eht was eH
.nageb eh dnA ”!seog ereh tub“
,dneB tesnuS rof tniop gnikarb a tog s’eh tuB
.esruc a rednu devil lrig a
.ereht tuo saw lla ti ypeerc woh tuoba kniht ot emit evah d’uoy
?ereht saw ,tuo yaw a t’nsaw ereht neht ,esac eht saw taht fi
”,thgirlA“ ”!taht htiw tratS
dna ti ot dedda kcart tliub-esoprup fo stib htiw
?wonk’y ,morf thgil worrob dluoc uoy srac rehto ynam taht t’nerew ereht os
,ereht tuo gnihtemos saw ereht tub
.yrots a tog ev’uoy“
,lla retfa ,emit tub gnihton dah ehS
leehw eht skrej ykciR
.oot ffo saw noisserppus erif tnaem
.tuanortsa eht ta
,cirbaf fo lluf os syawla selbidnam ym htiw ,em gniraeh ton tuoba tnemmoc emos ekam d’eH
ti tsac dah ohw ssertnahcne dekciw eht dna
dedoc ehs ,yllaniF
,ereh eb t'ndluohs I
,selat llat draeh d’eH
,tuanortsa eht dias
.yawa yats t'ndluoc I tub
”remrahc eniuqe eht ,foohnorI mok’aT“ yb daer
,erats deye-yklim a htiw mih sexif esproc siht ruoh na selim 002 ta dnA .esproc gnittor a ekil daed flaH
,das dna lufituaeb htob eno evah ot retteb eb dluow ti
saw siht tahw s’taht fi—lleps siht kaerb thgim gnitpurretni tuB
,dnuora semoc eh nehw emit sihT
,sekarb eht no tup ot seog eh sA
sihT“ .htaerb peed a koot dna
.sreirrab eht otni nips-dim saw eh nehw rac sih ot tuc ylno saremac VT ehT
seno tnatropmi erom eht dna
,epytotorp pot nepo
.denaorg dna derrits tuanortsa dnoces ehT
.yrgna eb htob d’ew neht dna
,ti tuoba od ot dediced dah ehs tahW
,dnal ffo raf a nI
.ereht deid ydob reh dna
,”ttub blubthgil“ ym mih llac d’I dluoc I fI
.ti ot gnikcits saw eh dna
,emit tsrif a steg enoyreve esoppus I“
,ti fo tuo kaerb ylno ton ot
.nwod era snoitacinummoc ym tub
.ffo dna no gniknilb sthgil eht ees I nehw elims ot tub pleh t'nac I
.thguoht eh naht egamad erom nekat dah troppus efil
,lluh eht tsniaga deniar enots dna eci fo stnemgarf ynit dna
.flesym tneiroer ot elggurts I sa em dniheb yltnetopmi hctiwt
.rehgih pu enihs sthgildaeh ,wonk’Y .tib a pu rac eht fo eson eht sekop hcihW
.suoires ton s’ti taht flesruoy ecnivnoc nac uoy nehw evael ot reisae s’tI
.tnatsni na rof ylno tub
.derit tsuj s’eh
.selggog ,tius thgilf ,taoc loow eguh
das yllufituaeb a tub
yad yrev taht ro
.erus ,tey tfel t’ndah yeht taht gniyrrow saw tI
.em dnuora esolc sgniw kcalb ynihs ees I
”!dioretsa na no er’ew kniht I“
.spal gnikam strats dna kcart eht otno ,stip eht fo tuo sdaeh ykciR oS
.esohc ehs tahw dna esohc ehs sa edoc dluow ehs
.neercs gniliaf eht no weiv otni selkcarc pihs sih nehw dnuos on s'erehT
.moor enigne eht morf deohce eciov tnereffid a
)sdleihs eht naht rehto( gnihtyreve nwod rewop tpecxe ,taht tuoba enod eb ot gnihtyna yllaer ton ,hcihW
”.gnol erofeb ti teg ll’uoy ,yrrow t’noD“
seirrow sih htob tuo denut
,dessap dah yad a neve erofeb swodahs fo kcis-flah ydaerlA
.yawnur eht ni noitaludnu na stih eh dna
.negyxo suoicerp pu tae dluow erif A
,efil ot ekoms ti was dna
,stenroh ekil depoows spihs ymene eht dna ,noitacol s’pihs eht deyarteb nwodtlem amsalp fo eralf a dna esuf nwolb a nehw dnA
dna ecar eht ni tfel sruoh wef a
.yawathgiarts tnorf eht otno tuo kcab dna
,sthgildaeh sih pu gnikcip era yawnur eht no seye stac ehT
rednit ot resal tup
nwo reh tub cigam on erehw
,erif eht yb etarc latem a no taes a koot noillats eht ”,kniht I“
”,gniteem a rof emoc ot yaw gnoL“ .saw
.desufnoc dekool god ehT
.ereht tuo krad si ti
”exe tod ttolahS“ dna
.em ot semoc evol ym
,doow derrahc dna sehsa fo elip a tub edisni gnihton dnuof yeht
.dah yeht negyxo hcum woh rettam t’ndluow ti krow t’ndid siht fI
.s’05 eht ecnis ereht gnicar neeb ev’yehT .hcus
.tiusecaps on erow eH .yawrood eht ni
evitpac desruc roop eht
.seldnac detnecs nomannic rof tsugsid reH
.devirra dah elpoep eseht yaw emas eht
,dneB tesnuS otni gniog rac eht skcerw ylraen dna
…thgin eht ni thgil tnatsid a ekil
.meht no thgir eyesllub a tup d’taht ,llac ssertsid a dnes t’naC .degamad oot pihS
.hsinif ot gniyrt ,dnuora gnivird tsuj er’yeht dna
,thgiartS namllU eht nwod sdaeh eh
’.erif fo dnik thgir eht‘
.nekorb neeb dah traeh reh thgin eht rennid rof netae dah ehs tahW
.rotcod a ees ot thguo yllaer eH
?tuo meht tiaw ot evaH
.stros lla dna sdnuow ydoolb eguh ,ekil dah tuB
gniteeM ediseriF“   yojne esaelP
”.seirots egnahcxe ot ereh eb ot desoppus er’ew taht“
s’erehT“ .yllacisyhp ,htom eht ot noitanalpxe eht ssap ot gniyrt fi sa ,sdnah sih daerps noillats eht
”.god retsam noegnud eht ,kcilliK“ yb daer ”,floWcaM boR“ yb
slaunam wef a dna
.rebmahc eht fo dne rehto eht ta ylferif suoicsnocnu derujni eht dna ,htom eht ,noillats eht deciton neht ylno dna
,wonk’y ,tiftuo tolip rethgif 2 raW dlroW dlo siht gniraew saw yug eht dias retal eH
gnidnats esroh a saw ereht
,meht fo tfel s’tahw ro ,sgniw yM
.uoy knaht ,tey tsuj lla ta slarenuf yna evah ot erised on dah ehs
,thgilnus eht nees dah ehs ecnis
.pu peek ot elba eb t’ndluow sdleihs degamad ydaerla eht reivaeh hcum tog ti fI .won roF
,sthgildaeh eseht dnA .ti s’taht tub
eb ot ti rof tnaem dna erif a edam tsuj uoY
flesti esae neeb evah dluow ylerus ti
,nehwemos ,erehwemos
,floWcaM boR eno dna
,reh nopu emac esruc eht
.enod dah ehs tahw ,devil dah ehs erehw ,nrob neeb dah ehs erehw
.luos s’ykciR otni thgir
.swodahs eht was eh ,was eh tahw wenk ykciR tuB
.deggurhs neht ,worbeye lacizziuq a desiar noillats eht
.tnemirepxe evitaroballoc wen siht tuo gniyrt rof ,renetsil ,uoy knaht ot ekil dluow lla ohw
”,lufraF lacsaP“ yb
thgin eht fo elddim eht ni hcraM ni dleifria na s’ti sA
,devol ehs shtym eht llA
.lla dna neercsdniw on htiw ,ytilibisiv drawtnorf doog yllaer dah ti saw tniop sulp niaM
llew evil dna ,evil ot deen thgim ehs taht lla htiw dellif
.ees nac eh lla s’tI
.tsif lacinahcem yllaitrap a dehcnelc eh dna
erif fo dnik thgir eht tahw wonk t’ndid uoy fi neve
thgil der A .trofmoc llams a s’tI .tsael eht ta
.siht ekil em ees ton eh rehtar d'I tub
daehklub eht no deraelc ecaps latem tub ,level etiuq t’nsaw roolf ehT
.kcalb hctip s’ti dnA
”?erif eht til uoy nehw enoemos gnitcepxe t’nerew uoY“ ”?tahw …ahW“ .tseb sih did dna
.liated elbirroh tsal yreve ees nac eH
.enilffo saw troppus efil ,tiaW
”,mrywkooB irikeneN“ yb
.esaeler reh tceffe ot eseht esu ot rettam elpmis a eb dluow ti taht
.ti rof nur a ekam t’naC
,efas dna mraw tlef taht
,dnim sih pu edam eh oS
,dlrow edistuo eht ta swodniw eht fo tuo kool ehs dluoc ron—
,lufraF lacsaP ,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
,gniht eht niw ot gniog ton s’eH
.relevart wollef a ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.kcart eht ot txen thgir doots s’enoemos ekil skooL
,dnopser ot desoppus saw eh derebmemer htom ehT
.sgniw nekorb dna annetna tneB
?morf emac uoy reverehw og …ew nac …I naC“
.derewopme ,demrofsnarT
yltniaf gnirrits ,tuanortsa dnoces eht ta decnalg eH
.ot mih wollof t’ndluoc I erus saw eh taht metsys rats a rof tfel eh oS
”!nrut ruoy ti sekam tahT“
.ycnaf gnihton ,s’08 eht ni kcab epuoc desolc ecno saw
,esiwrehto em dlot eh hcum woh rettam on dnA
decnyS .taebtraeh sih ot emit ni gniknilB
.ecaf sih ees t’ndluoC .erugif krad giB
.noinuer ruo derutcip I yaw eht t'nsaw sihT
.srats ynam oot htiw yks eht ekil ,neila tey dna
?reh ot taht saw tahw neht
,noinapmoc sih hsuh yltneg ot tseb sih did ,revo dehsur htom ehT
sgniht fo segami tsac ohw
daed enog s’oidar eht skniht eh ,oS
.delkcuhc ylno god eht tub ,detarepsaxe dekool noillats ehT
?deb fo tuo steg eh sa daeh sih fo kcab eht fo noitcelfer eht
”?hguone doog taht saw ,oS“
.mih dellik ylraen nmaD
,srenroc eht ni G4 ot detcejbus gnieb t’nerew uoy fI