,epyt eht htiw ytirailimaf gnol fo eutriv yb ,deifitnedi yletaidemmi saw tI
.kaelb er’yeht fi nevE
”.yaw taht emac yeht wonk t’ndid
”?oot ti draeh uoy woh fo trap“
!nac I sa tsaf sa gniog ma I“
”,sedart lla fo flow a ,traH ydrA“ yb daer
,dlrow rieht revo gnikat ylwols saw rotareneG
.erac t’ndid metsys eht tub
,erehwyreve morf detnaw ti tahw koot tI
,tsiggurd lufpleh eht dias
,toof no ecnatsid gnol dna surtic dna enimsaj htiw derovalf aet deppis ehs ”,enigami t’nod I“
”.enod ti draeh ev’I taht“
”.won yb hguone naelc deliob neeb s’ti regaw d’I ,gnirps gninnur a morf ti tog I“
,koot yeht sotohp eht dna sessam eht fo stsop golb dna steewt eht dessecorp tI
,drawrof denael rekihhctih ehT ”?nigeb ew llahS“
,ytiugibma gnisu yB
.xob eht no ’AHCTOG‘ drow eht etorw dna nep a pu dekcip tsicamrahp ehT .devresbo eh
,sthgil htiw gnuh duolc fo htaws a ekil liat
,krow nwo sti gnittimbus detrats metsys eht sa tide ot txet tuohtiw flesmeht dnuof ylneddus rotide eht ,ti htiw dna
,dessecorp dna no dewehc saw atad erom dna erom sa retteb tog stluser eht dna
”?trats ot desoppus er’uoy woh taht sI“ ”.nemA
.suoicipsus erew seye s’flowsedart ehT .rekihhctih eht dias ”!aet ylno s’tI“ .mih
”!?taht ekil skool ti nehw diarfa eb ot ton em llet“ ”,seye eht lla“
”,etal evirra lliw ti ,eludehcs dniheb raf os gninnur“ dna
”!ot tnaw t’nod I !etal evirra uoy fi neppah lliw tahw wonk t’nod I oN
,esruoc fo wen gnihton saw sihT
,gnidliub saw ti tesatad tnaig eht ni esu dna laets ot sgniht fo tuo gninnur detrats ti nehw dna
,ecov ottos ,dias dna retnuoc eht ssorca denael tsiggurd ehT
.tfel sretirw dna stsitra on erew erehT
,retteb tog ylwols rotareneg yrots ehT
.dlot era seirots erehw detinuer tey eb
,thgin rehtona dnats dluow ti desseug dah rekihhctih flowerew eht tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.enola hguone llew evael ot dediced hcihw ,murouq renid eht ot deriter egraM
.ereht reven erew taht sliated dda dluoc uoy
slaoc eht ediseb gnitsaor drahcro laref a morf derednulp d’eh selppa fo elpuoc a dna
I yaM“  .remotsuc gnuoy sih pu dezis ,ellezag dega-elddim a ,tsicamrahp ehT
.elppa tsaor sih otni nirg sih deirub rekihhctih eht ”!sselehtenon
.elpmis etiuq yllautca s’tI
”.dnah tfel ym htiw etirw I ,mmU“ ,gniylper
!taht ekil em ta kool t’nod esaelp dog hO
.ereht ydobon saw ereht ees ot nialp saw ti nehw ton ylniatreC
,elttil a tsael ta
.sub eht riaper ot stpmetta citnarf sih dna srettam eseht neewteb noitcennoc eht ot sa thgisni on dereffo tub
.tes nus eht sa ti ta llits saw eH
”.yawyna ,ti draeh I woh s’taht ,lleW“
”.erehpsimeh nrehtuos eht dna tceffe siloiroC eht denoitnem uoy nehw ti desseug evah dluohs I“
?hctaw ot meht rof seivom dna soediv swen gnitaerc neeb dah ti dezilaer elpoep nehw dnA .erew yeht
,enog saw sub eht esirnus yB
,sgninaem gnitaolf htiw driew neeb syawla dah ti dna
drawot dednetxe gum gnimaets eht ta dedda eh
,ereht tuo erehwemos ,dnif ll’I taht tbuod t’nod I dnA“
”,hcum os sknaht ,hsoG  ?yllaeR“
”.erehpsimeh reporp eht rof ssendednah tcerroc eht esu ot
,paehc emac ti dna ,tra dah yehT
.ralupop emaceb taht eno eht saw srieht tub
ereH“  .remotsuc gnuoy sih fo tnorf ni decalp eh hcihw xob llams a detceles dna retnuoc eht htaeneb dehcaer ellezag ehT
.tnatsni raen saw ti tub
.nagro elam eht dnuora flesti tsiwt ot noitanilcni larutan a sah modnoc a ,gnitsurht gnirud“
”,ereht gniog em dah erus uoY  !ah-aH  !hO“  .hgual
”?erus uoy erA“  ”.thgiR“
.elam redlo eht deriuqni
:thgin lla kcolb enigne eht dnuora pu deohce eciov siH
.hctawtekcop etacirtni na detlusnoc tsitra eht
,esirnus erofeb tsuj sriaper eht dehsinif dah leafaR
.46 yawhgih fo redluohs levarg eht no pots a ot tsaoc sub loohcs a dehctaw amohalkO ,keerC gnissiM fo stnediser eht
,reittiw drow hcae ,reprahs enil hcae
”,emit elohw eht uoy gnisaet neeb ev’I ,noS“
,decnuonna dna moorhtab eht morf degreme tnahpele gnuoy eht ,retal etunim A
yks thgin gnitfihs yltneg a ot meht denrut dna
”.sregnif ruoy no eseht raew ot nalp uoy sselnu dnah ruoy tuoba gniklat t’nera ew ,noS“
.tceffe siloiroC eht ot eud desrever si noitcerid eht erehpsimeh nrehtuos eht ni taht eton ot gnitseretni s’tI
.edistuo deppets eh sa devaw dna tekcop sih otni smodnoc eht deppils notlimaH  ”.niaga sknaht dna
.eno ddo na saw leafaR
.ytilaer rorrim ot nageb tI
.dloh ew snoinapmoc eht ,raeh ew seciov eht“
.eergasid dlrow eht gnittel fo
.htraeh eht ni erif eht saw
”.llew sa yaw ym no saw I emiT“
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM dna ,floWcaM boR ,traH ydrA yb sgnidaer gnidulcni
,erafraw gnag morf gnidih ni reciffo remrof a saw eh taht detaluceps emitemos dna
,flow citsitra eht derewsna ”,ebyaM“ .reh dniheb saw liat esohw ehS dias
”,sotcrA susrU“ yb ”noissecerP“
.desufnoc dekool flow citsitra eht
siht ekil nori fo tib dilos a enigami d’I
”,yrots fo tros uoy yrev a saw tahT“
.gnihtyreve saw ti dna
”.esuoh eht no era eseht os
fo xob a ekil dluow ,hu ,I“
ymotana yknow htiw sgniward ni gniredner stpmorp gnisuma morf edam semem
”?ti t’ndid ,hguoht gnicnivnoc dednuos tI“
.thgil fo olah a ni dehsinav dna efil ot delbmur neht dah hcihw
,ytirohtua htiw tsicamrahp eht denialpxe ”,ees uoy lleW“
.desolc yltneg seye dna daerps smra
,ti daer elpoep erom sa dna
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM“ yb daer ”,floWcaM boR“ yb
,remotsuc rehto ylno eht no gnitiaw hsinif ot tsicamrahp eht rof detiaw eh elihw
”?nup a ton er’yeht sa gnol sA“ ”.ekoj edurc a rO
eceip evitaroballoc a si
.revirdwercs taht htiw dooh eht rednu gniod yltnerruc saw eh revetahw ot tnaveler yeht erew ron ,decnedive yaw yna ni erew evoba eht fo enon hguoht
,hu I“ .niaga ecno deksa ellezag eht
.edis rehto eht no dednal reven
,doog yrev t’nsaw yrots eht fi ,sulP
.ni deppoh kcub tibbar gnuoy gnikool-suovren a
,htiw krow ot hcum os dah ti tub
enorht a sa gnisu eb ot demees eh kcap savnac nrow eht morf drawrof denael rekihhctih eht ”,lleW“
.eerf si dlrow siht ni edam gnihton tub
,raeppasid ot tsal saw liat reH ”.lleweraF
,devorpmi saw metsys eht ,nooS
,si naem I tahW  …t’nod I  …hU“
,lewort gnitplucs eht dna
,ffo saw ti ,laerrus saw tI
,detcirtser si sinep eht ot wolf doolb eht taht ereves os semoceb gnitsiwt eht hcihw ni detroper neeb evah sesac ,tcaf nI“
.erom ecno skeehc sih gnihsulf doolb ,deddon notlimaH
,ti dnuora nwot eht lla dah sa
.noitnetta sih thguac taht emem suoiralih a
.deknilb notlimaH
yrots a s’tI“ ”?ekoj kcid A“
”,thgir ro tfel yas t’nseod tI“
.nup a t’nera yeht sa“
,dab saw metsys eht fI
”,gnirpsyaD seyethgiN“ yb
”.gniht fo tros siht rof tsuj ereht ni peek I taht rorrim a s’erehT“
.tsiggurd eht dias
,floWcaM boR“ yb daer
.erif eht gnikop naht rehto snoitacilppa emos was
”,llew yreV“ ”.thgir yM“
,gnirpsyaD seyethgiN yb snoitubirtnoc htiw
,kcoms s’tsitra na ni flow a delbmurg
.taht seod syawla dnim namuh eht esuaceb ni llif dluoc niarb eht dessim ti sliated ehT
.eerf saw ffuts yknoW
.deksa rekihhctih flowerew ehT
”,erofeb tem ev’ew secalp eht naht reddo oN“
.rekihhctih flowerew eht derewsna
.elims ediw a htiw remotsuc sih ot kcab ti dednah eH
,deralced dna degreme eh
,tuptuo eht devorpmi srotaerc eht ,desu seuqinhcet eht fo tnemenifer hguorhT
,elbmessaer ylevitciderp dna trapa pir ot hcum os
,emit eht ta renid eht ni eb ydaerla ot gnineppah fo eutriv yb murouq utpmorpmi na demrof ohw—
,ytilaitnedifnoc fo ria na htiw deksa dna retnuoc eht ssorca denael ellezag eht niaga ecnO
”.eromyna em gnitruh fo elbapac s’taht retaw eht ni gnihtyna s’ereht“
.enigne eht htaenrednu kcab sih no ,noitats sag eht ta cinahcem enol eht
,ereh llew eb lla teL“ .rood eht drawot denrut dna gabloot sih detfil eH
taht saW  .rorrim a ni gnikool erew uoY“
.oga elihw doog a
sdrac gniteerg fo kcar llams eht ta gnippots ,selsia eht hguorht derednaw eH
.laer eb ot evah t’ndid ti dna ,yrots retfa yrots detsop ti tub
”?siht dne uoy woh taht sI“ ”.nemA
.amohalkO ,keerC gnissiM ni ton yllaicepse ,neppah t’ndid ylpmis sgniht hcus yawyna dna ,elbaticxe eb ot nwonk saw taog gnuoy ehT
”.egamad tnenamrep ni gnitluser
,enilno dias saw tahw tpada ot dah tsuj tI
.mih ta erats dereugaeleb ,deiraew
,gnimoceb ti tuohtiw yrots a llet ot elbissop ti si ,yas d’I“
gniteeM ediseriF“   yojne esaelP
,dehgis yllanif ehs ”,tsael tA“
,tuoba deklat dah ti yteicos htiw gnorw gnihtemos rof puorg a demalb ti nehw dnA .erew yeht
.dlot era seirots erehw ereh llet draeh evah ew sA
,floWcaM boR dna ,sotcrA susrU
.namsedart flow eht detnemmoc
,tuo gnirekcilf nugeb dah ruf reh ni sthgil eht ”,gnol sA“
.rotareneg drow eht no denrut yeht
,gnol a delevel reh dniheb saw liat esohw ehS
,hguone ylsuouconni detrats ygolonhcet ehT
.ecneidua na dekooh taht yaw a ni tuo dewolf swen eht dna
.devirra dah ehs sa yltbus sa
,nrut a ot enod won ,selppa eht fo eno debbats eH
.oga sraey elpuoc a ,sub eht ekil hcum ,nwot otni nwolb dah flow ehT
.slooc siht erofeb doom eht nethgil nac I fi“
,tnorf eht ot dnuora rednaw ot hguone dipertni luos ylno ,senoJ duB yb kcab detroper saw ti nehW
.decnahne neeb dna denrael dah IA eht tub
,noitareneg tra dedecerp dah noitareneg txet
,pu tohs seuneveR
,neht elpmis demees dah tI
?eh dluohs yhw os
.denrael metsys eht dna
,nwad desselb eht naht lufituaeb erom erew eh dna“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
dlohserht eht ssorc ot detfil eh wap ehT
.dlot era seirots erehw
,lacigol t’nsaw llits tI .tuo eno tips ti
,tsrif ta lacitpeks erew elpoeP
.yratnemucod yhsalf a htiw dednopser ti erofeb sruoh wef a koot ti dna
ssensuoicsnoc fo sedom terces gnicart sedoid ro snoitalletsnoc nwonknu gnimrof srats erew esoht rehtehw hguoht
.meht ot gnihton diap ti dna gnitepmoc-tuo ylwols saw ti stsitra eht neve
,gnineppah saw siht ekil gnihtemos elihw gnikooc kcab eht ni yats ot detcepxe eb t’ndluoc ohw kniks ,nosrednA einnA
,eeffoc sih morf pu kool ot nwonk neeb sah yentihW dlO dnA
,dlob dna suoegaruoc gniciojer wolleb dna ,seciov fo yveb a si eciohc fo nopaew esohw
.skeehc s’mredyhcap eht ni elbisiv ylraelc saw hsulb ehT
.erif eht esuod ot retaw fo lufelttek rehtona tuo deruop eH ”.llew hA
,llaw renid eht no kcolc eht yb MA 54:01 tuoba ,dr3 rebmevoN fo gninrom eht nO  ”!saedi yna teg
,desolc ylluf rood eht erofeB
.tuoba deklat elpoep tahw emaceb detcerid ti evitarran eht
,dias rekihhctih flowerew eht ”,ees s’teL“
”?dednah-thgir ro tfeL“ ”?em esucxE“
”.yrgnuh m’I dna yad lla gniklaw neeb ev’I erehw trap ehT .haeY“
.eef a rof yllausu dna
”?kool a flesruoy evah dna moorhtab seeyolpme eht ot ereh dnuora emoc tsuj uoy t’nod yhw os ,thgir siht teg ot deen ew“
.tsoc elbirret a dah tI
.erots eht fo raer eht ta retnuoc eht dehcaorppa notlimaH dna tfel namow dlo eht tsal tA
”?rehto eht naht rewol sgnah selcitset ruoy fo hcihW
.flesti evorpmi ot tenretni eht morf atad gnillup dna stpmorp gnitcelloc
,dloc dna ,krad ,ytpme saw
.delims dna remotsuc sih dniheb rood llams eht desolc eH
!esnes on sekam enigne sihT
,detniap dah stsinoisserpmi eht woh s’tahT
,eussi na saw ti dias reven metsys ehT
,ssenihtrowtsurt ot deifitrof aet htiw
.teef reh ot tog ehs sa moor eht fo srenroc krad eht ni detfihs liat reh fo sthgil suoropav ehT
.sselehtenon yrots a s’ti tub“
?nialpmoc ot gniog saw ohw tuB
taht detaluceps emitemos dna
.atad eht rof gniyap t’nsaw ti tpecxE
”?uoy t’nera ,siht ta wen er’uoY“
”.reh dniheb si liat esohw
.tniop a ot delttihw
bup denodnaba eht neht dna
,won sedaced emos rof denodnaba neeb dah ecalp ehT
,olliramA morf yaw eht lla emoc ot gnilliw eb ylekil dluow kcurt wot on taht dediced
”.nrevaT denodnabA eht ni gniteeM ediseriF“ saw sihT
,sretirw dna srevol
”,yroeht ni ylno fi ,eb raen lla su tel oS“
rekihhctih eht derewsna
,zurC leafaR dnuof ,revewoh ,gninrom gniwollof ehT
.reH dniheB si liaT esohW ehS devresbo
”.ti tuoba thguoht yllaer reven ev’I“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
.desserpmi naht ssel dekool eH
.eb ot thguo tcirtsid loohcs a fo eman eht erehw revo delicnets ”11:2 ccE“ ,hguorht pees ot gninnigeb saw tsur eht erehw secalp wef a ni sniats nworb hsidder ,wolley lanigiro eht pu revoc ot tniap etihw ettam :suB hcruhC a sa
tnatxes eht ediseb dna snep yhpargillac eht htaeneb morf
.lla ti did ti dna ,od ot ti deksa uoy tahw did tI .detaerc tI
”,syaw eht fo eno s’tI“
,deggurhs eh erom tnemom a retfA ”.risseY“
.ereh llewd ew sa gnol sa
?detnaw enoyreve hturt eht eb ton siht dluoc woH
,gum nit sih ot gnipleh suoreneg a dedda ylregae rekihhctih flowerew ehT
.levarg eht ni skcart erit ylno ngis a rof gnivael
,suouconni demees etisbew ehT
,sisahpme rof retnuoc eht no regnif sih deppat ellezag ehT
erofeb tnemom a rof thguoht notlimaH
,pots yaw ruof a ta srevird suovren ekil
moor nommoc denodnaba eht fo swodahs gnirekcilf eht hguorht dednapxe liat reH
,tuo ti tips ti dna dias saw yeht gnihtyreve koot tI
,eciton ot tey od t’ndluoc enihcam a boj a gnikrow neht ysub oot saw rotide ehT
.moor ytpme eht ot rekihhctih flowerew eht deddon
.keerC gnissiM ni denodnaba gniht tsrif eht eb t’ndluow tI
,gab sih fo tuo lanruoj a dehsif flowsedart eht
.taht od dluoc ti
.klaw s’yad flah doog a rof snwot eht lla deedni dna
,etunim rehtona retfA  .niaga ecno moorhtab eht otni deppets elam gnuoy deretsulf ehT
”rekihhctih flowerew
9491 yluJ  ”.slooc
,wodniw renid eht tuo yltnatcepxe reep ot dna
,gniog erif doog a dah eH
”?siht si tahw ,tiaW
ksam sih ffo nekat dah ”nam llat“ eht taht
.ffo erew sliated eht ezilaer t’ndluow uoy
,kcurt wot a gnillac tuoba noissucsid emos saw ereht elihW
.sraey rof ereht toof tes dah eno on fi sa
,yks thgin a hguorht wons fo skaerts ekil ruF
”,teem ot ecalp ddo na si sihT“
.ytilaer fo lla demusnoc tI
.taorht sih deraelc tsiggurd ehT ”.esaelp smodnoc
.lacisnesnon ro driew saw detaerc ti tra eht semitemos fi neve
,dluoc namuh yna naht rekciuq dna retsaf gnihtemos od dluoc IA ehT
,tsiggurd eht dias ”,nos ,kooL“
”.kcab thgir eb ll’I ,em esucxE“ ,dias eh ”,nmaD“
.gnibmulp elam sih ot egamad tnenamrep fo thguoht eht deredisnoc eh sa srecuas sa ediw sa erew seye s’notlimaH
,esnesnon sa dessimsid erew
,hguoht ,saw erehT
”,nos ,ti noitnem t’noD“ .notlimaH dias
.ti morf gnitpada dna gninrael tenretni eht deruocs metsys eht elihw eud rieht rof deksa srotaerc eht dna
,dellats dah sub eht erehw ot del skcart eht elihw ,ylsuoiruC
.seno lanoitcif eht tsuj ton dna
tuoba detnar ylduol eh
.levarg no pots a ot gnillor serit fo dnuos yna ta
.denaorg flowsedart eht ”?yllaeR“
.ffuts eht yrrac t'noD“
.hgual doog a edam ti dna
.flesym yb pu naelc ot em tfel uoy fi nevE“
”,smaerd gnilwoh eht“
,did ti tahw htiw melborp a nees reven dah ti ,yawynA
,wal eht morf nur eht no saw eh taht detaluceps emitemos neeb dah tI
,retteb erew seirots eht
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
bup dlo eht ni thgil ylno ehT
,redluohs sih revo lehctas s’retniap epacsdnal deppiuqe-llew yldnuoforp a
,sub dellats eht morf renroc-yttik spets hcruhc eht morf ylsuonimo gnihctaw lluH ardnaS evas ,nwot elohw ehT
”?rekop ecalperif a teg uoy did erehW“
:daer ot nageb dna ,ti denepo
”,neht ,htob uoy ot slevart efaS“
”,rab eht dniheb ti dnuof I“
ylneddus dna deparcs ti egami hcae htiw txet tuoba gninrael neeb dah rotareneG trA ehT
.tnalahcnon kool ot gniyrt ,erots gurd llams eht otni deklaw notlimaH
,neht eef rieht rof deksa srekam ehT
,mih dehcaorppa ,denrecnoc ,egraM nehW
”.enif tsuj krow dluohs esehT  .nos ,og uoy
.yrtemoeg naedilcuE-non dna
,hU“ .deriuqni eh ”?uoy pleh
?cilbup eht gnidaelsim rof elbisnopser dleh eb srotaerc eht t’ndluow ,gnorw saw metsys eht fi ,sulP
wohs eht dnif ro
,daolnwod dluoc ti gnihtyreve elots tI .denrael ti dna
”!seye dna erif fo edam sgniw htiw
.lio rotom dehcrocs fo llems evitcnitsid eht dna ekoms hsieulb gniwollib rof evas ytpme yleritne pu dellup dah sub ehT
”?yrots fo tros ruoy
,tnedive saw eciov sih ni tnemelzzup ehT
,od ot tem er’ew tahw ton s’tahT“
.yldaorb delims tsicamrahp ehT
,txet eht dna segami eht detaerc tI
.trams erew yeht tub
erew seirots detubirtnoC
.yrots wen a etaerc syawla dluoc metsys eht
.flowerew eht delkcuhc
,sehsa fo llems eht dna maets fo ssih taerg a saw erehT
.noissecerp sa nonemonehp eht ot refer ew ,edart eht nI
,leef t’ndid metsys ehT
,ytivitca lauxes degnolorp gnirud ,etar yna tA
.yppah saw rotide eht dna
detinu era tsal ta sretirw dna srevol dna srethgif dna sredaer nehw
.noisufnoc ni worb sih pu deworruf notlimaH
,deddon rekihhctih ehT
.rettam eht fo hturt eht dezilaer eh nehw flesmih ot deddon dna elihw a rof trap tsal siht deredisnoc eH
.gnihsilbup erew yeht yrots rieht htiw enilno tsop ot hguone doog saw taht tra fo eceip a dnuof dna ,semit wef a etareneg dekcilc
.deksa eh ”?wollef gnuoy ,uoy rof od I nac tahW“
.noitats sag eht ta cinahcem on neeb sah ereht yad taht ecnis ,sselehtreveN
.feiler htiw dias eh
?ytilauq rehgih ta snoitareneg retteb ehT
,dehgis ellezag ehT
uoy dna trops doog a hcus neeb ev’uoy“
,larom saw gniod saw ti tahw fi metsys eht deksa srotaerc eht fo enO
.retnuoc eht dnuora notlimaH dereets renwo pohs lufpleh ehT
,dab saw enoemos dias ti nehw dna
”,hguoht ,raf siht tuo ti ekam ot hguone suoiruc saw esle enoyna kniht t’nod I“
,ereht yrots a ylbaborP
.tnahpele gnuoy suovren ylsuoivbo eht dias ”,haey
.detaerc dah ti tahw ni lla ta dab gnieb rotareneG trA eht tuoba gnihtyna t’nsaw ereht ,swen eht ta gnikool tuB
.suoivbo eht gnitats erew eh fi sa remotsuc gnuoy sih no nwod dekool tsicamrahp ehT
.ti tuoba gniklat neeb evah dluow aidem eht ni enoemos ylerus
,tpmorp a ni deppord rotide na taht metsys taht otni saw tI
”noddegamrA“ daer ngis noitanitsed eht taht
”.dezis egareva ,seY“
,kcab tra ylno evag tI
.rehpog elamef ylredle na
”dniW eht retfA tiusruP“ dna
.xob eht detcepsni notlimaH
.ssel emaceb tsitra na rof deen eht ylnedduS
,flesmih detniap ,gum nwo sih dellif dna ,rethgil ylbaredisnoc ,ksalf sih kcab koot flow eht ”,siht sI“
.did syawla ti hcihw ,melborp a saw ereht fi enoyreve llet dluow tI
”.elbatrofmocnu etiuq emoceb nac ti
.lavirra sti no sub eht mialc ot eno on erew ereht fi yllaicepse
.derrumed reh dniheb saw liat esohw ehS tub
.devirra stseug sih fo tsrif eht erofeb
”.did erus tI  .ris ,seY“
,repap ot krow rieht gnittup dna ,gniward stsitra erew ereht ,eruS
,tsrif gniog fo ngis yna rof owt rehto eht ta gnikool meht fo hcae fo tnemom a retfA
.ni knis ot sdrow eht rof sdnoces fo elpuoc a koot tI .dettimda eh
,srethgif dna sredaer tahT
.erutaef lanif a dedda srotaerc eht ,sweiv hguone teg t’ndid taht nehW
.letnil ylredle eht rednu dekcud eh sa
”.ereh retaw eht tsurt t’ndluow I“
.niamer ton did hcum yrev sevlesmeht ohw ,revird dna sregnessap saw deniamer taht noitseuq ehT
,sub eht dedraob dah leafaR taht smialc reh erew sa
”.ti htraenu ot ecneitap dna emit eht dah eno fi
.flowsedart eht dias
tub pleh t’ndluoc notlimaH ,dah neeb tsuj d’eh taht dezilaer yllanif eh nehW
.esorp elbassap etirw ot woh wenk ti dna
.wollef gnuoy ,ylniatreC“
uoy fo rehtie erofeb ,nigeb ll’I oS“
.htraeh eht fo edis rehto eht no taes a koot reh dniheb saw liat esohw ehS ”,hguoht
semalf eht revo gnitaeh elttek a dah
.did ti tahw tsuj saw taht ,lleW
.sruoy fo htob raeh ot sdeen ohw enoemos
,dlot ti seirots eht fo xim eht ot ysrevortnoc dda ot ytiliba eht metsys eht evag yehT
,dednopser flowsedart eht
,erif eht otni denotni eh
,denworf flow eht ”,toN“
,eerf saw tI !derac ohW
.meht gniximer ylsseldne dna senil dna sdrow tseb eht gnikcip yrrehc
,sekorts daorb eht ees ot hguone esolc t’nerew uoy sa gnol sa dna
,noob a saw IA eht tuB .yenom tsoc tahT
lativ si ti hguohtla
.lehctas sih morf ksalf derettaps-tniap a dessap flow eht ”,ereH“
.eerga ot dednet srevresbo owt on
”?dednah-thgir ro dednah-tfel gnideen eb uoy dluoW
”.eno deen uoy fi ,oot moorhtab eht ni relur a
?dedeen dna detnaw enoyreve tahw yltcaxe saw ti fi noitaerc eht noitseuq ot eh saw ohw deksa dna detnaw enoyreve hturt eht detaerc dah ti taht deugra IA eht ti nI
,yad ym edam yllaer
,gnihtemos tuoba yrots a rof ti deksa uoy nehw
.raew rof esrow eht hcum yrev dekool flow ehT
.llif ton did thgilerif fo hsalf a stnemom revetahw ni
,naeM I tahW wonK uoY fI seidaL ehT nI detseretnI toN saW eh
”?thgir ro tfeL  ?ti si hcihw oS“
”,uoy ot slevart efaS“
,lliw I  .ris ,seY“ ”.erom deen uoy nehw kcab emoc dna sruoy fo ydal ykcul taht htiw nuf emos flesruoy evah og tsuJ“
.dnim yna stnemetats reh gniyap fo tibah eht ni saw ydobon dna elbaticxe eb ot nwonk saw taog gnuoy eht tub ,enigne eht ta
,noissecerp ot tnatsiser era hcihw smodnoc poleved ot yrtsudni eht delbane sah ecneics ,yletanutroF“
.slaoc eht morf yawa ti detfil dna
”!kaelb tib a saw taht lleW“
,deunitnoc dna ecaf s’elam gnuoy eht no kcohs fo noisserpxe eht deye tsiggurd ehT
,ti gniod seno ylno eht t’nerew yeht dna
”.ti evah ot thguo I ekil kool t’nod I sediced poc a fi snoitasrevnoc drawkwa ynam ooT .yvaeh ooT
.ytilaer nwo sti etaerc ot detrats rotareneG trA ehT
?uoy t’nera ,siht ta wen era yllaer uoY“
”,tahw uoy llet ll’I“
,yaw eht ssorca rab eht ta roteirporp dna rehsifgnik ,riadA egraM
.seirc etarepsed s’flow eht erongi ot denimreted demees
.dettimda notlimaH ”,ris ,seY“
renid eht ni tuo gnignah tub gnihtyreve morf deriter mussop ,yentihW dlO dna
,eciov a dias ”,ereh m’I“
noitnetni on dah eh dna ,hguone dnuos saw htraeh eht taht dna
,rehcnar lacol dna godpeehs ,senoJ duB yleman —pihsredael nwot eht
”?gnimoc esle enoyna sI“
,retteb tog metsys eht fo noitareti hcae tub
.flesti taeper ton dna won ylsseldne etareti dluoc ti atad hcum os deparcs dah tI
,yad eno neht dna
trA ehT .ffo pord ot detrats tog yeht stneilc fo rebmun eht tub
”?thgir s’rorrim eht ro thgir ruoy
”?llet uoy nac woh
.hturt eht emaceb rotareneG trA eht taht neht saw tI
,krow suoiverp no tliub lla saw tI
,dnah sih ni gabloot s’namsedart a dna
s’erehT  .seiceps ruoy fo elam a rof dezis egareva era uoy emussa I dna“
.ksat wen a ot ti tes srotaerc eht
kcits a dehsidnarb rekihhctih ehT
.gninruhc tpek detroppus ti ytinamuh ni etah eht dna
.srotaerc sti fo noitcerid eht ta hturt sti otni deximer elpoep fo snoillib fo egdelwonk eht dna
.ti evael ot dediced saw ti oS
,dennirg flowerew eht ”,on hO“ ”?ecalperif eht ediseb“
”rotareneG trA ehT“
.deraeppa renwo s’eciov eht retal tnemom a ylno dna
,ereh tnemeergasid a fo tib a saw ereht yas d’I ,devirra I nehw ecalp eht fo etats eht morF“
.desirprus tsael eht saw ydobon
”nrevaT denodnabA eht ta
,detaerc ti hturt eht ylno saw erehT
,swen eht emaceb tI
,tsiggurd eht dias
,erif eht dorp ot
.t’nsaw ti neht tpecxe
”.esoppus I ,trats a ekam ot hguone si eerht“
,dda ot denetsah neht ehS ”.nup a t’nsaw ti“
taht smialc s’lluH ardnaS .yawa del enon
yrots s’yadoT dna
.devorpmi yrtemoeg eht ti htiw dna
”mrots a pu ’nissuc seye on htiw ksam a dna tah a htiw nam llat“ a saw ereht demialc lluH ardnaS
.daeh sih koohs rekihhctih ehT ”?lohocla oN“