.klof ’nipeels eht ot yrros ,haeY
!sbuc ym ot emoh teg ot
,ydob ykcots ,egral a dna
,elbissop sa drah sa etib
.rewsna na stcepxe taht dnuos fo dnik eht s'tI
,ecroF esnefeD arretoxE eht ni reidloS namuH
”?yawyna ,pu eno taht kcip uoy d'erehW" ".emoh
,dellats dah remmus eht fo tluassa ehT
,lla ti sees eh dna mih nekat sah dniw eht
,tniop siht ta derettam taht fi sa sroloc grubspaH ni
-tcilfnoc ecaps peed rof tnaem t'nsi gnitolip er'uoy pihs eht
,namuh a tub lla saw eh oga syad eerht tsuj
,elihw a rof no wehc ot gnihtemos meht evig ll'ti ,hE"
?egarag ot tolhctiws ot drayliar
.senil elttab neeb evah ot thguo taht selbmahs eht gnoma ylsselmia gnirednaw reidlos erom eno deciton ydoboN
,sdrow sih ni deilpmi gninaem a saw erehT
.elihw a rof nus eht ni yrd ot meht gnidaerps dna sedis eht tuo
"noitavreserp-fles ton ,latnednecsnart
- yllaer ton ,serac eh taht toN
,nepo seye s’ykrapS
,erifnogard keerg fo noitanoted yb tfel dnik eht ,wolloh elttil A
.tahw rettam on mih detroppus I mih dlot I
esuoh ’stnerap yttihs sih fo tuo mih kcuns I emit eht ro
”,su segnahc od ew gnihtyrevE“
.roolf eht no swaperof sih gnitser yllanif
,xof etihw a eb ot tsrif ta demees tahw ot noitnetta rieht denrut htob dah
,mih tnereffid a ,tnereffid si eh fi gnirednow
ydob s'tnahsaV-aleeT hguorht dehsur taht kcohs dloc ehT ".em
.ytud gninaelc fo tuo teg ro
,roolf eht ssorca eldnurt raeb fo sdnuop derdnuh xiS
.tuo meht tros ot ypareht fo sraey sekat
,ffo mih tuc flowerew eht ”,ereh er’uoy fI“
,remrahC eniuqE eht
.teef sih ot tog noillats eht
,enozo suorecros dna redwopnug fo gniknits ,yddum ,dloc
”?eeffoc stnaw ohW“ dna ”,rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR“ yb daer ”,floWcaM boR dna ,seirraH loS ,ykrapS yb ”sserpxE 522 eht fo noisnecsA“
,ereh fo tuo yaw a eb dluoc siht gnipoh tsuj saw I“
,ffo pir nibac eht fo edis eht ot slenap eht
,raw eht morf emoh eb ot desoppus saw eh erofeb gnol ,tsafkaerb ekam ot tnaem ylno dah eh fi sa
noitativni sa ecnelis desufnoc s’regdab eht koot noillats ehT
,seirraH
”,xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD“ yb daer
,erifpmac a derekcilf nihtiW
hguoht" ,deklat eh woh tsuj eb thgim taht hguoht
.did ydobyna taht ton
.smaerd esoht dah eh ekops ew emit tsaL
,esion emos edam eh drol doog dna
.mih htiw yradnuoB eht ssorc ot ydaer saw I
.seiceps rieht fo nemiceps enif a saw eh
.citats fo tsrub a saw erehT "-.srM"
.sknab etisoppo eht erutpac ot deliaf dah
…yks eht drawot esir ot nageb
.gniht erom eno dna ,hO"
,skcart eht fo nogard dlo ehT
,stlob gninthgil fo ovlas A
,si noissim ruoy tahw mih llet ot gniog er'uoy
,od ot tnaem eh tahw taht regdab eht ot derrucco tI
.gniraef neeb d’eh naht reisae yllautca saw pu rotalocrep eht fo pot eht gnikcip os ,thgirlA
.gniht-xof desserd-llew eht dias
,ograC  ?eciojer dna
.krow ot etal eb annog m'I sseuG"
neht dna ,esuap a s’erehT
.sliar eht hguorht srevihs sdnes taht
,flesmih ot skniht eh
…mih ksa tsuj ,noitingoc namuh ylluf ,lleW
.namuH neeb dah nam siht ,seY
,epacse ot detnaw eH
.ereht ydobon dnif ot ylno
?wenk uoy thguoht uoy dlrow eht fo dne eht siht t'nsI
.reh delbuort siht
.yrots a gnirb dna
.emit eht lla serif hcus edam srewollof pmac dna sreidloS
,flowerew eht dedda
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
s'taht dum hcnerf fo teef evif mialcer ot
.emoh og em tel yeht dna revo wohemos ylneddus saw raw eht fi neve rO
,sllems eht semoc nehT
”.snoititsrepus …ekiL
erif a thgil ot saw pets tsrif eht
,modretsamrehgrub dna ycarcuaerub dna egaggab fo
.serac ohw ,sretlif fo elpuoc a s'ti ebyam ,KO
:seilf ti woh ho ,seiks eht fo
,noillats eht dias
fracs sepirts dna srats eht gnizingoceR
shtnom rof ereh gnitiaw fO
,rednammoC eht ot troper ruoy evig
noitcepsni s’tnemom a hguoht
.emoh gnidaeh er'yeht detpecca evah ot smees tegraT"
.pu dekool xof reppad eht ”,lleW“
.tnemom a rof erif gnilkcarc fo dnuos eht htiw ria eht ni gnah yrots eht tel regdab ehT
,dleifelttab siht no gnoleb t’ndid ylsuoivbo ohw
.tnedicca yb rekcits dnoces a tnes I kcuF .kcuF
,ti rof degnul ehs ,denepo rood ehT
.elosnoc eht tsniaga flesreh decarb tnahsaV-aleeT .koohs pihs eht
.no desserp eh os
,dael dilos otni detumsnart ylgnizinoga sgnul sih
.moor lanoitaercer s'pihsrats ssalC-D eht ni ylsuovren decap tnahsaV-aleeT :nageb ,saw eh xof fi ,xof eht dnA
esnopser lanoitome eniuneg a fo noitacidni ylno eht saw
.ereh snogard gniklat er’ew
.ti eteled tsuj ll’I enif s’ti os tey segassem sih dekcehc t’nsah eH
.nottub kcalb gib eht tih ot sdnecsed neht
.thgir ton …lla er’yeht tub
,naem I" .detats ehS ".flesruoy
nomoloS“ yb daer ”,ykrapS yb
.tnemmoc ot esufer I"
gniteeM ediseriF“
.ereh eb ot desoppus m'I taht"
,tnemegaruocsid fo tnih on was tub
thginot tuB  .sgniht hsinif tsuj
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.enihcam eeffoc eht fo pot eht no thgila swap sih tsrif
,esiugsid eht porD"
,taorht sih no ruf naht rehtar selacs deciton
,demees ti ,htaed neve toN
evil ylneddus thgim
,retnuoc eht no srevotfel
:sneppah ti litnu retsaf dna retsaf ,niart eht tfil ria eht gnitteL
.efil reh htiw tuo ti ekam ot ytinutroppo na dah llits ehS
.teef deromra-etalp sih fo dne eht ta swalc suonitarek drah ylbissopmi ot latem morf evlover sevlah tnorf eht
,gninrom eno denruter ylsuoiretsym saw rehtaf rieht fi dnA .lla retfa
emit eht lla dne sgnihT
,yenruoj tnereffid yrev won a no sregnessap
,slaes eht lla fo rednusa gniraet eht siht t'nsI
.sehcnert eseht fo tuo yaw a dereffo
.roolf latem eht fo ssenlooc eht
,ylwols ekaw sraeB
.em no detset ti evah ot dereetnulov I
.eeffoc htgnerts raeb :yadoT
aixelA' .eman taht htiw ecaf thgiarts a peek t'nac I ,yrros m'I-"
.siht tuoba gnikniht eb ot tnaw t’nod I
,eeffoc dnuorg fo gab eht rof psarg swap ,pu txeN
,god a fo htmraw eht
.detats reidlos ixargaV ehT ".namuH
.ti hguorht gniltsihw
.dias eh ”?tahw woN“
,nosrep ni uoy ot klat ot tnega na gnidnes m'I"
,seirrow ,snoitanimaxe ,stseT
”.seod raw sa hcum sa tsuj uoy segnahc erif siht ta gnittiS“
,noitca ni gnissim esoht gnoma
.seert detnuts wef a llits erew ereht erehw
,roolf eht rettil sdnuorg dna sretlif eeffoC
.skoobeton ym no meht tup dna
”.dneirf ym ,ereht uoy ees ll’I spahreP“
.rotalocrep eht fo pot eht otni meht steg eh ,nael suoiracerp a htiW
.flesruoy detalimissa ylgnilliw ...uoY"
”.esol ot gnihton dah I thguoht dna
,rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR
,mroftalp eht no uoy ediseb nam eht shgis ",nmad lleW"
,srotartlifni delliks tsom s'elpoep reh fo eno saw ehS
,reciffo gnidnammoc sih ohw dna
.eganoipse rieht no pu hsurb ot meht llet nac uoy os dlrow emoh ruoy ot kcab uoy dnes ot gniog er'ew neht dna
"?erofeb namuH a detalimissa yllufsseccus
,worbeye demoorg yletalucammi na desiar xof-tahwemos eht ",tahT"
”?uoy t’ndid ,yllacol dna
.moor eht dnuora kool yliggorg ot gnitfil daeh
.dnuorg delbbep eht tsniaga gniniarts srepeels detlob rieht ,gnilbmert skcart eht ,enot suorednuht A
.gnol os rof ti denifnoc evah taht sliar eht morf ti gniniahcnu dna
,pot ralucric eht gnippirg sdapwap talF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ecno tuo meht detnirp dna repap rekcits s’loohcs eht desu I
.srednow fo lluf nac hsart a
.ti gnidih ni tniop on s'ereht
.sraeb ot tnatropmi t’nera sgniht eseht tub
,sdnah sih gnurw regdab eht ”,wonk t’nod I“
.emit tsal eht rof sdnuos eltsihw ehT
.enihcam eht otni ti sekam ti fo tsom ,lleW
”.ereh eb llew sa thgiM
reve uoy evah ,aleeT ,em lleT"
”,syaw etarapes ruo og ew woN“
,evila yats ot woh tuobA
tnedicnI emirP xargaV eht morf relggarts a gnieb fo yrots reh tpecca t'ndid snamuH eht
.ti saw taht ekil leef t'nod I tuB
,enod eb dluoc ti fi
.dluow reidlos namuH a sa desserd saw eno siht hguoht
.tsuj ro tihs erov orcim
’,siht od nac ew
,foohnorI mok’aT
gnitartlifni fo elbapac dna ydaer htob seiromem detnalpmi
,decar dnim s’regdab eht ”,llew ,hU“
.ydaerla dednopser s’eh tuB
:mih rof redro tsehgih eht fo levon llits lla si sihT
,htiw laed ot drah oot sleef taht tub ,ereht gniht gnirusaem lil a s’ereht swonk eh woN
.deksa I nehw deilper reven eH
,roivaheb namuH deiduts dah ehS
.sgniliec s’esab eht no daeh sih gnignab ylraen
”.era sromur tahw s’tahT
,ti raeh lliw sniart rehto ynam woH
,tilps sleehw eht fo sevruc nori tsac eht tnatsni na ni sa
,sucum htiw gnippird
",uoy ot pu s'tahT“
snoitubirtnoc htiw eceip evitaroballoc a si yrots s’yadoT
drazil gnitlom a ekil
htiw snamuhateM fo rebmun gnisir ylidaets a tog ev'ew os
.riaffa fo dnik yranoitats a t’nia nogard a otni niart a gninruT
.sov-keT maraX ,rotartlifnI
.moor lanoitaercer eht otni kcab devom saw ehS ".evoM"
.taht erofeb remmus eht dna
.tegrof re’en lliw yeht
,sgniw sti gnikaerb ylwols erofeb pan eltneg on
.edis hcae morf elcric latem eht dnuora gnilruc
,tnemom raeb a retfa ,yllanif ,nehT
.til ydaerla eno dnuof eh tuB
,gnidneb leets fo ,sevom eh nehw snaorg gnikaerc taerg ehT
,ria gnivom yltfiws htiw etalfni sgniw sa eerf gnihcterts
”,taht tuoba yrrow I“ ”.yrroS“
,ekop eht teg ot ediced od uoy fi wonk em tel dnA"
rotalocrep eht morf nwod gnitlit daeh
seegufer nailivic dna ,srewollof pmac ,srennur noitinumma
.neppah ot gnihtemos rof gnitiaw dnats t’nac I tub
yrots a fo etirwer a detrats yltnecer ohw
",noitacol eht rof eyesllub a s'emeht eht ,lleW“
,esnepsus htiw dellif tnemom a rof srevoh
”.cauoviB draugraeR eht ta gniteeM ediseriF“ saw sihT
,moor eht ni gnirewot ruf dna elcsum fo teef neves ,sdnats raeb eht
.gnitseretni ti ekam tsael tA
ro eseehc hcum oot ,ysetuc ooT
".tsujda uoy pleh ot dnuora enoemos tnaw annog er'uoy
...emirP xargaV ot kcab gniylf nageb pihs eht sa degagne smetsys tolip-otua eht dna
toos leseid htiw deraems dna dekac si ylleb siH
-snug yna evah neve t'nseod ti
,flesmih srewol raeb ehT  .ecalp otni ti etator ot seganam seirt wef a retfa
ta dekool ehs sa denediw seye reH
,yromem ot siht timmoc ot uoy tnaw I dna
.yrots eht gnillet eno eht er'uoy"
,tfard eht gnidiova enoemos tuoba saw ti dias morf
.meht esu llits I
.hguoht ,sromur s’reidlos lla er’yeht"
saw ti ekil leef I
,xofnogarD reppad eht ,nelarD yb daeR
.spil sih ot regnif a desiar dna
,delpuoced dah pihs eht detacidni redduhs a
”,mmirG flokarD“ yb ”noitartlifnI“
,kcol sleehw eht sa skcart eht gnola ylf skrapS
,sknub rieht ni gnipeels nem
.erom yna tuo mih tel t’nod stnerap siH .mih
.detcepxe sa saw sihT
.walc deppirgdniw sti ni thguac
raeb ehT ?gninrom sihT
”?meht ezingocer I lliw
mih deksa ydobon tuB
,foohnorI mok’aT“ yb daer
,rotalocrep nori tsac tneicna s’esab eht ot emac eH
,eppurgnetsimehcla naissurP a yb dellik teg ot
.deggurhs flowerew eht ”,did I ebyaM“
.mih rof eb ot elba reven saw I taht syaw ni em rof ereht saw eH
.detcejretni esroh eht
,hcnurc dna rettalc setalP
neht dna ,GNALC cillatem a htiw enihcam eht no ti steg eh ,ti gnitfiL
,drawkwa si gnidnatS
?t'nsi siht yas ot s'ohw hcihw
.sneercsoloh eht ta daeh sih revo gnikool ,taes eht fo kcab eht tsniaga denael dna dneirf sih dehcaorppa nairdA .dekramer eH ".emoh
,ytiniffAruF no noitcif trohs laerrus gnitirw si dna tsiyasse na sa flesmeht gniysub si ohw ,anueL yb ”gnihtemoS rof gnitiaW“
.skceB ot txen ton ,siht fo yna tuoba kniht ot tnaw t’nod I
…troper sih evig ot ydaer
,KO’  .raef dna rednow fo xim a htiw ti no gnizag
.enim laoc gnispalloc a fo rednuht eht ekil gnigniS
,retfa yletaidemmi tsomla dna
,edakcolb tsrif eht tsap ti edam neve t'ndah ehS
.edisni eht morf nwod ti gnignirb dna
?thgir ,seirots evah tsum uoy neht“
?hcum oot em degnahc ereh gnieb saH
.setats tnereffid thgie-ytrof fo tirg eht dna
”.dad regdab yldduc
.enolcycosem a ekil gniraoS
?elbatibahninu erofereht dna desruc-elpirt eb ot tuo nrut ot gniog ylno
tuo gniyrc smaeb degrofremmah
tsuj dluow ehs hsiw semitemos I
”cauoviB draugraeR eht ta
.kced noitavresbo eht otno kcab debmilc eh sa nairdA degdelwonkca ylerab dna ,srotinom eht no yawa ylf pihs eht dehctaw sucraM -'krawluB'
,desserd ylbaccepmi
.GNALC duol a htiw
,pihsrats dereednammoc eht fo slortnoc eht neddirrevo ylno ton dah dna
:slaog sah ykrapS ,taht dnim reveN .drawrof dehcnuh
.efil ot sgnirps rotalocrep eht
?era lla uoy revetahw …ton m’I fi nevE
.erehwemos trats ot evah seirotS“
,yawa nwolf toN .enog saw dna…
,rekcits esuom elttil ym ta kcab kool I
,yltnecer pu taht dekcip uoY
,daeh rieht fo kcab eht gnola gninnur stserc dennif trohs fo riap a ,selacs neerg htiW
ydob eht nwod gnidacsac selacs laever ssalg deniats dna leets fo speews oced-tra eguH .sgniw gnimoceb
,noitats ot noitats ,toped ot toped
tuoba gnikniht m’I
,nageb regdab eht ”?tahW“
,enihcam eht ni sdnuorg eht fo tfel saw tahw spmud tsuj raeb eht os
,espylacopa yrev eht ekil gniraoR
,spop suonigalitrac ot yaw evig snaorg latem eht ,kaerc sgeL
,god eht fo htmraw eht gniyojne fo tnemom a retfA
.yks deniatsekoms eht hguorht setaludnu eh sa
”?saw dlot tsuj uoy yrots eht kniht uoy did tahw“
,noitisop detaes a otni gnitoolpS
,flesreh gnimlac ,ni dehtaerb ehS
.rorroh ot denrut kcohs dloc ehT ".edisni
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,drazil orhtna na eb ot detnaw syawla I
.eeffoc edam raeb eht gninrom sihT ?gninrom sihT
.taorht sih deraelc
ycnamorceN fo sproC ymrA yb desiar troppus lateleks eht gnoma—
,lwoh a emoceb s'ti ,sedaf neve ti erofeB
,noicipsus ni neve citamsirahc
”.seirots egnahcxe ot erif a sthgil txen enoemos revenehw ro reverehw oT“
,ssenhcir eninac sih ni kciN
,hcuot fo ssenerawa eht semoc tsriF
.ecnahc eht ta pmuj d'ohw htraE no su fo snoillim s'ereht
.seips ruo era 'strevnoc' ruoy fo flah tsael tA
,mmirG flokarD yb
.eromyna aedi on dah eh taht ytsenoh tcefrep htiw dias evah dluow eh
,stfil waperof thgir sih
,tnelis tnew tinu mmoc ehT ".gnitseretni
,spetstoof draeh ehs ,moor lanoitaercer eht otni edorts ehS
.rehtegot llits er’ew fi mih ksa ot gniog m’I fi rednow I
.llih eht fo pot eht ta enots eht otni detlem neeb dah
,god.ecioveht ta
”,egnahc fo gnikaepS“
.yas ot retteb gnihtyna evah t’nod I nehw esu yllausu I eno
.deksa tnahsaV-aleeT "?yratilim namuH eht ni srotcefed llac yeht tahw taht sI" ?namuH A ".edagirB
nevaeh wen a yb dedeeccus eb ot
,pot retemaid ”81 eht no esahcrup dnif ot elba era swaperof htob ,nwod gninaeL
”.yrots a htiw emoc evah“
,sllup dna kcats eht no talf dap mlap sih secalp eH .retlif eht ,KO
.srekcits nwo ym denoissimmoc reven I .nigeb ot
.yrots rehtona si"
eno siht draeh I yug ehT“
.ereh eb ot dereetnulov d’eh fi sa t’nsaw tI
.roolf eht no dloc eb ot kciN gnivael ,sesir ykrapS
ria eht hguorht yltneg gnirettulf dna derettacs si ,won tnavelerri
,remrahC eniuqE eht
,taoctaerg sih htaeneb morf sgniw ylacs eguh daerps eH
,depeeb tinu mmoc s'pihs ehT
.esiop detfol sih woleb tfirda ,lla meht sees
.wolg derarfni mraw htiw ezalba
"?ni AND rehto ecilps ot woh tuo erugif ot stsigoloiboneX eht rof gnitiaw uoy era ro
,elbmur dna deeps fo ynohpmys a si sihT  .sniartnogarD
rekihhctih flowerew eht
,rehto eht ro yaw eno ,sgnileef on dah eh dnuof eh tuB .noitresed saw
,sknab yrellitra eht dniheb
,dedda dna -ecaf ixargaV a ot ngierof noisserpxe na -dekrims nairdA
.wolloh eht fo egde eht ta gnirevoh regdab eht ot denokceb eH
.etummoc tsal eno tuo sevres evitomocol eht sa sgnap robal fo noitacove s’nimereht detnemrot a ,maercs sliar ehT
?won sraey ebyam …ni t’nsah eH
,elam ixargaV a
.ti tuoba tuhs shtuom rieht peek ot hguone revelc erew
,lleH ?em ezingocer sdik ym lliW
.dehsinav dna ,yawa pets ot denrut eh sa ,noillats eht dias ”,era ew revetahw er’uoy esruoc fO“ ”?cigam yna od t’nac I fi nevE
,retsaf ,on ,dereenigne eb nac sa tsaf sa kcart eht nwod gnimaercS
,kced noitavresbo eht tfel nairdA ".haey ,haeY"
.noisicerp lacov denoh-llew dna smargoloh thgil drah hguorht mrof dna smsirennam 'seiceps rehtona gnitceffa fo elbapac
,ni gnittes saw nmutuA
.emoh ti ekam od I fi neve ,skrow siht fi nevE“
.dediar ixargaV uoy eno eht ,wonk uoy
.sessalc hguorht rehtegot em gnidloh saw eh ekiL
.sreyal etaciled ni meht ot gnimoc ssensuoicsnoc
temoc a dnuora sdioretsa ekil mih tsap detfird
.eciov namuH elam eht ot noitome elgnis a yarteb ton did tnahsaV-aleeT ".eman a tahw ,wow
sromur draeh tsuj d’I
s’nam-on fo redrob eht ta sdraw eht ssorca yllacitehtapa derettiks
,emoh nruter ot gniyrt
.ti dah eh ecno thguoht taht tuoba
thgin ta dloc saw ti
,sretummoc dna laoc fo sllems eH
egrahc sseltniop a ni
,won rof tiaw ll'I"
”.dneirf ,emit ni tsuj devirra uoY“
?egrahc ,desivda-lli tsom dna ,tsal eht rof
.snoitseuq lareves desiar sihT
,tnatsid dednuos ydaerla eciov esohw
,uoy htiw tnulb eb ll'I ,kooL"
,nekat saw tnuocdaeh a nehw ,gninrom eht nI
?rewsna lliw ynam woH
,ynoloc inadirE nolispE eht no sgol eht morf gnissim detroper saw taht pihs a sehctam noitangised eht dna
,esroh eht dias ”,no gnaH“  ".krow
.revetahw ro hcnub a ni srehtaef sih teg ot tnaw t’nod I
"?metsys rieht gnitartlifni su tuoba reh def uoy tihsllub taht fo lla saw tahW"
,brubus dna eludehcs fo ,stekcit dna selbatemit fo dlrow enadnum
.roolf eht ot gnirettulf
yteicos eritne ruoy
”,tsum uoY“ .kcab knarhs ohw
,ti tset ot dediced stsitneics ruo fo eno
.roolf drah eht no gnikcalc swalc
,remmus tsal ekil tsuJ
.kcab emac eh nehw emas eht saw reven eH
,pihs eht tfel dna pu doots nairdA ".era
.dneirf tseb ym htiw ereh m’I dnA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,deggurhs rekihhctih eht
.yltnereffid emit gnicneirepxe si eh fi
.deilper sucraM ".haeY" "?haeY"
denrut noillats eht tub
”.eb ot desoppus er’uoy neht“
.swaperof nwo sih ta kool ot
?em rof krow lliw taht …dnA“
erew seirots detubirtnoC
,tnahsaV-aleeT" .degilbo ehS ".ti
gnihtyna erehw ,htrae wen dna
,etavirp detsilne na ylerem ,regdab elgnis A
,seno ecim fo skcap emos era ereht ,skcus tI
nogard eht gnitfil
,kcolB eht dessorc ew emit eht tuoba kniht ot tnaw t’nod I
,nibac eht tsniaga gnihsur dniw eht gnileef
.sreh htiw dekcod yltcerid dah pihs A
.stnemknabme yrellitra eht dniheb sllih eht ni dnuof erifpmac a fo stnanmer eht erew rehtieN
ehcatsum rianobed ylbatupersid eht htiw noillats eht dna
,ytniatrec htiw ekops namuH ehT ".dediar
.xof eht deerga ”,ylniatrec hO“
",erus ton m'I" ".ebyam ,emit txeN
,gnol gnihcterts ,niart eht gnola gnippir ,mrof egnahc yeht kcab gnilluP
evotsdoow eht ediseb seirots raw gnillet
.leets dlo dna tsud fo
,xof-tahwemos desserd-llew eht dias
.tnereffid s’eh won dnA  .tahw won dnA
.t'nevah uoy esuaceB" .detats ehS ".tnemmoc
,ggarB nairdA" "?uoy era ohW
potretnuoc eht ot ti gnippilf neht ,ffo ti gnitsiwt
,dednetni reenigne on syaw ni tcatnoc otni decrof
.narreT tcefrep ni deksa ehS
.sdnoces ni dnuorg eht no mih evah d'ehS
,llew ,su ta sDAB ruoy gnidnes tpek uoy nehw os ,ti rof seiceps nwo rieht yarteb ot gnilliw s'ydobon ,esruoc fO
sbuc regdab eseht ,llew
.skraps otni devlossid dna dnal-
”,era uoy esruoc fO“ ".ereh
.ykrapS dna ,seirraH nomoloS
.raet suoicoref a
,saw ynapmoc sih erehw mih deksa d’yeht fI
dloc ytrid elbaresim fo
,scidem ,srenoisivorp—
mrof s’niart eht morf llup dna pir slenap sa
,kcab sih gnola senips eht ot gnilc serugiF
.yako gniog era sgniht epoh I
.tinu mmoc eht dehcaorppa dna
.slirtson evitisnes-ylwen sih otni redwop yhtrae eht fo seton esnetni gnitfaw
.senorD noitalimissA lacigoloiB eht fo noitatimil eht wenk yeht
,wolleb gnitepmurt a
,seilfnogard s’taht ,haN
.namuH ton er'uoy setacidni osla cinap fo kcal ruoY"
.desu eh srekcits elttil eht htiw deppots eH
,krow dluow ti thguoht yllaer I kniht t’nod I
,raey a dnuora ni gniees eb thgim ew taht
,seno wen tnalpmi dna seiromem rieht elbmarcs ot snaem a sa ecnatsiser s'tcejbus eht sesu
,daorliar eht gnola gniohce
sehtolc nrow-daor dna ybbahs eht ni flow ehT
,siht gniyas flesmih dnif ot enoyna naht desirprus erom saw regdab eht
.tseuqer snoitacinummoc a gnikam erew snamuH eht gnitacidni
.ruf sih hguorht elbisiv ylraelc erew snroh nailitper tah sih deppit eh nehw dna
,yrehtael gninrut latem eht
!won dna ereh ot pu er’yeht gniht a s’noitamrofsnart nogard ot niart“
.elbakramer yaw on ni deredisnoc saw
.flowerew ybbahs eht deksa
.lla dna puc gnirusaem
?siht fo esoprup eht saw tahW
.htaerb peed a koot regdab eht ”,thgir llA“ ".yrots
elpoep eerht erew ti dnuora dna
.dne reh morf tpursid t'ndluoc ehs taht rehtet lanoitativarg a ni tpek tub
elcric tilerif eht dnuora decnalg eH
.seno drib ylbbircs elttil eht ,dekil eh seno eht rebmemer I
,gnihtemos uoy llet em teL
,gnivorppa ylmraw dednuos noillats eht
"?regnol hcum ereh tpek eb ot gniog I mA"
dna liat eht ot desu teg ot keew a sekat ti
.ssem a si nehctik eht ebyam ,oslA  .duorp si
,sDAB ruoy ,krow fo eceip ytsaN" .deilper nairdA ".t'nevah
,'levraM
”,sromur draeh uoy fI“
.taoctaerg sih htaeneb sgniw fo eniltuo eht dna
,ekop eht teg annog uoy erA" .desuap eH ".ereh
.deviecnoc ylbissop evah dluoc ron
.yraew yldnuoforp saw regdab eht dna
,taorht sih derab nairdA
.noitingoc namuh )raen( htiw raeb a si eh won
”,cigam od nac uoy esruoc fo dnA“
.gniwerb eeffoc evah sraeB
,floWcaM boR ,anueL
.rehtegot swaperof sih spalc raeb eht ,tnahpmuirT
.pu denethgiarts nairdA ".od lliW"
,thgiew sih gnitfihS
.pu kaeps ot gniog saw eh dezilaer eh erofeb dias regdab eht
.ti dnuora delruc wap sih ,fo dnik ,eno sah ykrapS ,rettam t’nseod ti ,eniF
.edagirB namuhateM
.kcen ym otni gnihtaerb s’ehs dnA
,dilots ,diats eht fo
erow ehs esiugsid eht derevoc taht htolc fo elimiscaf eht barg dnah a tlef tnahsaV-aleeT ".ixargaV a s'ti ,peY"
thguondaerD ssalC-A FDE-
.era yeht seno hcihw tuo gnirugif kcul dooG
,wob a tpews xof ehT
sllih eht dehcaer eh litnu
”.eno tuohtiw erif eht dnuof evah t’ndluoc uoY“ ”?tsum …I“
.emoh morf yaw gnol a s'ti
.derutpac neeb d'ehs ecnis nevig dah ehs
?KO ,hguoht sdrow llams esU
,regdaB eht ot denrut meht fo eerht llA
.pu dellup saw dna
,seod ti tahw tuo derugif
,seye otni spmaldaeh gniknilb ylipeels ,noococ evitomocol a morf gnigreme wols oN
".scitna ruoy ta ffo ssa reh hgual ylbaborp ll'ehs
erutnevda eht denrut etummoc gninrom rieht
.nwod tas dna riahc eht ot revo deklaw ehS ".tiS"
.ereh era srodassabma xxiG eht elihw su reuqnoc ot gniyrt pots ot meht teg ll'ti ebyam
.noziroh eht revo mrots tsud a ekil ria eht hguorht yaw sih gnilpmarT
”,hguoht ,egnahc retteb a s’tI“
.selamef tnanimod rieht fo smsirennam eht detceffa dna
.mih htiw xelpmoc ruo edistuo thgir tas I dna gniyrc thgin lla pu saw eh emit eht ro
"!reciffo gnidnammoc ruoy ees ot dnamed I"
,romur ot gnidroccA
,gnorw sleef thgiew sih
.ti no raelc erew enorD noitalimissA lacigoloiB a morf sracs eht
”-citsym fo dnik yna ton m’I tuB“ .dehgual xof eht
?noitalever taerg emos siht t'nsI
.warts tsal eht neeb dah tahT
.neeb dah eh erehw erif eht ssorca ecaps eht ta deknilb regdab ehT .dehsinav tsuj
.mih emalb t'ndluoc ...hcihW
.daed demuserp ,gnissim sderdnuh erew ereht
,seirraH nomoloS dna
mih rof ti dettink dah retsis s’nosrednA .tvp—
.romra dna yrnopaew yvaeh htiw nwod deggob reidlos namuH a ylekil ,yvaeh
,ni gnittes saw nmutua woN
,ti htiw gnimoc sretlif eht flah
yojne esaelP  .dad regdab yldduc a
.slatep gnillaf ekil