,layarteb ekil tlef dah tI
.hturt eht morf gniht tsehtruf eht saw layarteb nehw
,peed a ekat dna seye ym esolc I
,lwob eht sehcaer kaeb ym erofeb syas ehs ",guh A"
tar looc ,gnizama ehT
,em tpecxe snoegip on tuB
.em morf elbat eht ssorca tar eht ta kool I
.dlrow eht fo edis rehto eht rof evael dna sgniw ym no teg ot dedeen I tfil eht lla em evag regna dna
,yllaer gnihtyna ,llew ,fo tol a dah reven star ehT
.ti tuoba ssenipmurg lausu sih naht erom neeb dah taht tub ,star dekil reven dah eH ".kcab
.guh taht fo thgin eht no tlef I ssendas emas eht sa ,llew
,niaga teem d'ew depoh ev'I"
.gnidivorp ta elbirret ytterp si metsys erac eht taht gnihtemoS
erap-erp tseb uoy ,ekim eht ot pets ew nehW ereht atuo thgir ti kcep ,tuo ti kcep annog dratsaB yppalF
"?dratsab yppalf uoy ot
shgis fo tsetfos eht htiw sesuap dna
.reh erofeb smra reh sdlof dna riahc reh ni kcab snael ehS ".kniht
,em erofeb daerps srepap eht ta nwod kool I
.erom ecno retlaf dna ,niaga nigeb I ",I"
",gnimoher reffo nac I yaw on s'erehT"
worht t'nac uoY" .ti pleh dluoc eh ,tuo denrut ti sa ,dnA
llet ot evah ot gniog ma I taht dos roop txen ehT
.ediug a tuohtiw ezam a ni kcutS
.eciov citehtapmys ylgnimrasid tsom ym esu ot erus gnikam ,yas I
4991 ,omed desaelernu morf tprecxE *** .sdon ehS
*** .noitatimi on tpeccA snoitareti peeD .snoitatimil oN hahcaerp ruoy eb ammi netsil tseb uoy
"?uoy ot deneppah tahW" ...semoc ti ereH
elzzum reh ot esolc ti sgnirb ehS
?thgir ,ereht gnitteg regnol tib a dneps ot evah tsuj uoy ,eraf ria yap ot evah I
*** ".tsoor a fo mottob eht ni evil t'nac syug uoy tub ,pu uoy tup d'I
.dessap sah tuoemit gnimoher eht ,emitnaem eht ni ,dnA
.txen gnimoc si tahw wonk I
senil dehsinifnu ruoy hsinif
",oot uoy dessim evah I"
,rehtaf ym dna aralC htob ta gnihtees
,naem I .enola pirt ehT
.seilimaf rehto eerht htiw ti gnirahs er'yeht dna
dnatsrednu ot yaw on ev'yeht
,gnihtyreve pu dellif evah erif kcolb rewot eht morf elpoep ehT
.spup reh fo rehtaf eht emoceb dah
.gnihtynA .gnihtemoS
.smoordeb thgie htiw elbaliava gnisuoh fo laed taerg a ton si ylpmis erehT
,rehtaef eht ta gnirats
hguorht gnikcilf neeb evah I krowrepap eht morf pu ecnalg I ,ot resolc s'ti owt eht fo hcihw erusnU
.gnorw gniog lla s'ti
.swalC raelC ot yas ot sdrow gnidnif elbuort evah ot desu reven I
,emit emas eht ta neppah eerht lla semitemoS
seye reh sesolc ehS "--thguoht reven I tub
8102 desaeler
.rehtie won reh rewsna ot elba ton saw I
.kniht I klat ot evah eW .em htiW
.nruter dluoc I erofeb sraey eb ot gniog saw ti wenk I ytilaer ni nehw elihw elttil a rof yawa gniog tsuj saw I taht reh llet
,hA" .swapdnah reh htiw nwod srae reh snettalf dna pu sehcaer neht
.dedeeccus evah tsum I
.t'ndid I os ,taht enod evah dluoc I yaw on saw erehT
.reh morf raeppasid ot mees sraey eht dna
.eno toN .dias drow a toN
.decneirepxe dah fles evian ,lufhtuoy ym taht
.sreffo owt detcejer sah ehs
.yevnoc ot desoppus si eciov eht yhtapmys eht fo yna ylerab leef I dna ,hceeps desraeher a si tI ".ereh
,thgin taht tsoor eht ot kcab enog dah I .eM
tnemom elbirret tsom eht saw thgin tahT
si yrots s’yadot dna
.noitarepsed dna noitarepsaxe neewteb erehwemos enot a ni syas tneilc ym "!ssiM tuB"
.tneilc rehtona tsuj ton si ssalg eht fo edis rehto eht no nosrep eht taht esilaer ot
.detrats I erofeb taht wenk I
.seiduts eht otni
,em ta gnikrims reh dnif ot pu kool I
.tnemom a rof niaga seye reh sesolc ehs sa
.rehtaef eht pu skcip dna tuo sehcaer aralC sa
.retlaf dna ,nigeb I ",mhu ,I"
.tiucsib etalocohc a fo pot no ,su neewteb sdnal eno dna ,epacse srehtaef ynwod wef A
.weivretni desolc a htiw pu uoy tes ot gniog m'I"
,edih depleh dah tsipareht eht
.reh htiw yas ot sdroW
dah seye reh ni ssendas krad ,peed ehT
.od nac ew esle gnihton si ereht taht reh llet ot desoppus ma I
.elbisnes detnaw ton dah I tuB
.oga gnol os enod dah ehs yaw eht yltcaxe ,efil ym otni kcab thgir gnillorts ,niaga kcab ,saw ehs ereh ,won dnA
.em liaf yeht woN
.noitatibah elbatius on evah dluow spup eht naem dluow gnisuoh oN
:1 3 .loV staeB ssaB'n'murD laitnessE morf pool taeB :kcart gnikcaB
deneppah tahW" .noitseuq lacirotehr a saw sdnatsrednu ehs tbuod on evah I tahw ot seilper ehs ",dias I"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.tuo gnittel pu dne d'uoy parc fo dnik eht eb d'siht desseug reven I tub ,yppalF ,sruoh rof tips dluoc uoY"
...ot enoemos dnif ot evah d'I
,senohporcim emos
,sa peed sa ssendas a htiw em ta skool dna niaga meht snepo ehS
.dluow I depoh dah rehtaf ym tahw od ot ydaer saw I taht ,yromem eugav a otni gnivlossid ylwols noisserpxe reh
.taht reven ,tros citnamor eht toN
.gnihctiwt sreksihw reh dna ylthgils detlit daeh reh htiw syas ehs
,oY :2+1 .hgih nop yaw morf emoc eW :2 .haol nod yaw morf emoc eW :1 .traeh ay kceP :2 .rae ay walC :1  .uoy dratsaB :2 em dratsaB :1 .od ot woh su llet emoc ,pu etir emoc aY :2 .og ot erehw su llet ot rof pu etir ,pu etir emoc aY :1 .od ot tahw rof wonk ew ,eeB yppalF dna em ,oY :2 .hturt ed hcaet ot kcab emoc ,swalC raelC dna em ,oY
,eciohc yb eb ylbissop tonnac ti taht eveileb ot esoohc tsuj yeht os ,siht dnatsrednu ot mees t'nod srehto eht dna snevar ehT
.tsil gnitiaw a ydaerla s'ereht
.wonk ot sdeen licnuoc eht taht toN
"?tammos ro wohs a teg dna beeB eitnuA ot teg ot dah uoy yas ot esu ew t'ndiD
.niaga kcab er'uoy nehw hguone noos llaH erovhgienraC ni tips ot elba eb ll'ew ,eciuj revelc taht lla pu kaos ,ereht ni flesruoy teG
.nac I gnihtyreve dna gnihtyna od ll'I .t'nod esaelp ,oN"
sselemoh emoceb lliw ylimaf reh dna ehs tahT
.nwonk ev'I ecalp tsefas eht er'sgniw ruoy
.gnileef eht ylno
hguone gnol em spots tI
fi wonk t'nod I" .dias ehs ",htiw pu emoc nac uoy nosaer gnorw yreve rof ti gniod s'eH" .ssenhsop fo snoiton sih dna msicar sih dna rehtaf ym wercs esuaceb ,yawa nur ot gniog saw I taht reh dlot tsuj dah I
desab si gniht elohw eht dna ,esruoc fo ,eil evissam a si tI
eht no gnikrow neeb ev’yeht cipe if ics taht em llet yeht dna
,ysae eb ot gniog reven saw tI
yllanoisacco yrev eht morf sreciffo eht setarapes taht ssalg ytiruces eht fo edis siht no noegip ylno eht ma I
.rehtegot tup er'yeht woh wonk I tub
.eb ot dnet star etanoitceffa revewoh ,tros luftsul eht neve toN
.tcejorp EDK eht ni
ecaf ruoy ni pu thgir teg ot ereH
.snoegip ni suoivbo os tsuj si hsulb a
,dedeen yletarepsed os yeht pleh taht teg ot gniog ton erew yeht taht secaf rieht ot elpoep gnillet ,seciffo licnuoc eseht ni gnittis fo sraey ytnewT .dah I esruoc fO
neppah thgim tahw enigami ot raeb tonnac tub wonk I
.evil ot meht rof erehwemos dnif ot liaf ew fi
.raeh ot tnaw t'nseod yllaer ehs taht eno dna
.hcrep eht dnuora pu esnet teef ym sekam ti taht hguone lufrewop
.suonegorp ylsuoiroton era staR
.reh ton saw em ot deneppah dah tahW
,keehc ym sekorts dna tuo sehcaer ehS
.elbaliava s'tahw s'ti tub ,lamitpo ton s'ti wonk I
.oot ,gniyrt ma yllaer I
,secnetnes ruoy hsinif ylno ton dluoc ohw enoemos htiw dah uoy pihsnoinapmoc fo dnik eht saw tI
,edis rehto eht no ,wor eht nwod eno rehtona si erehT
.neht reh rewsna ot elba neeb ton dah I "...elttil
.si ti esruoc fo esuaceB .yas I tahw si
.meht fo pot eht revo taps ew dna ,senut eht nups dah
.gnivael erofeb ecno tsuj esolc reh dleh dna reh dnuora sgniw ym depparw I
.em ta kcab gnirats seye gninetsilg ,der fo riap a dnif ot
,yas ot snigeb ehs ",hsiw tsuj I"
.taht no ruoh hsur gnitnuoc neve toN .tfihs ruoh net a rof ,kcab dna ereht sruoh eviF"
erawtfos ecruos nepo dna eerf gnitaerc ro ,noitcif ecneics dna msilaer laicos fo stib suoirav gnitirw
.no su sdnes yllufpleh licnuoc ytnuoc eht sesruoc esoht fo eno gnirud su thguat tsipareht hceeps lanoitapucco eht eno tahT
taht dnatsrednu tsum uoY"
.emit tsal eno s'aralC ot og em tel ot deerga dna detneler dah daD ,yad txen eht tuo ylf ot eud saw I hguoht neve tub ,thgin yadrutaS a fo dne eht ta saw tI
.dah yllaer ti ,gnirettam deppots dah tI
demees evah thgim siht reporpmi woh morf edisA .syas ehs
,eno siht retfa erom ekil dluow uoy fi ,dnal ot taht rof gnitiaw elihW
swalC raelC m'I ,yrd eye ruoy epiw ,oY :2 .esab ot kcab etir ti gnirb ew ,efas saw uoy thguoht uoy nehw tsuJ ecaf ruoy ni kcab etir sdrow ruoy gnittips emoc eW
.somreht gnimaets a dna stiucsib fo etalp a yb decalper si su neewteb ssalg ytiruces fo enap eht emit sihT
reffus ot evah elpoep taht das si ti ,eruS
.ereh noitpo na eb ot sah erehT
deiduts I scitsitats esoht taht dnim reveN
dlaraH .pma paehc a dna rekaeps gib a
.dah reve ev'I gnileef tseB
.reh was I emit tsal rebmemer ot yrt I
.meht rof semoh wen rof snoitpo wen rof deleep seye ym peek I ,epat der fo spirts erom no gnipparts neewteB
,etamgnos ym ot eil ot dah I tnemom ehT
.sedaced owt tsal eht rof revo dna revo
.emoh kcab dah dah I tahw ekil gnihton erew ekam did I esoht dna ,sdneirf ekam ot deganam ylerab I
.pu gnipparw ot resolc gnitteg si edaced a fo tsom tsal
.loohcs doog yllaer a ot ,rednu nwod uoy gnidnes s'eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
,peed a gnikat erofeb kaeb ym kcalc I
neeb dah ti tahw morf efil ym gnicuder ta krow drah ym lla retfa noitcnitsid htiw detaudarg ,amolpid ym htiw denruter dah I
gnileef taht no detca dah I
.noitautis esuba labrev a rof ecnatsissa pu llac ot mocretni rosivrepus eht ta gnikcep morf em spots taht dna
,sgniw eht htiw eno eht saw I sa hcum sA ".ko m'I ,haeY"
.gnifoop eht pots ot deliaf yletelpmoc won yb evah I taht erawa yllufniap ma dna niaga pu kool I
.em sa emas retlehs dna doof fo deen ni stelgiwt fo lluf tsen a dna ,llew sa ylimaf a tog ev'uoy erus m'I ,yrrow t'noD"
...saw em ot deneppah dah tahW .dad ym toN
,erom neve tub ,gnimocebnu ylbirret si ti gniht eno roF
,esuoheraw a eb ot desu taht gnihtemos ni seirotimrod fo hcnub a s'tI
.guh taht ecnis ,llew
,uoy evag ew sreffo owt tsrif eht detcejer ev'uoY
.ti detseggus neve I erofeB
.sdrow eht no krow su tel ot gnilliw ylimaf eht htiw eno eht saw ehs tub ,htuom eht dah dah I
"?tol yrros siht htiw pu dne uoy d'woH"
.reh ecarbme ot elba neeb ylno dna
.ti fo yhtrow ton ,wohemos ,erew yeht dias
,hcuop a ni sgniht wef a nworht dah I
,enil eht gnola erehwemos ,yllautneve dna ,yawa rehtruf dna rehtruf ti dehsup I sraey ruof rof dna
.em rof esle gnihton neeb dah ereht esuaceb ,ti otni dah I gnihtyreve deruop dah I raey retfa raey dna ,boj ym enod dna enog dah I
,emit fo tuo sa ecalp fo tuo hcum sa ruls eht
.esoht fo eno evah seod aralC tpecxE
wohs eht dnif ro
.seye reh dniheb gnirif snoruen reh fo kraps eht ees nac I niatrec leef I dna
,llew sa eurt si ti tuB
,daeh reh sgnah ehs sa
metsys a ni kcutS
.ereht nwolf dna no ti depparts
.siht ekil snosaer lanosrep rof ssecca reh esuba naht retteb wonk ot thguo yllaer hcihw
,yalpsid desilivicnu yletarepsed taht retfa yldrawkwa sdaerps taht ecnelis eht ni niaga nigeb I ",m'I"
.srae ypoord won reh tsniaga srehtaef thgilf ydruts ym fo egde eht fo hsurb thgil A
.reh ekorts ot nrut ym s'ti dna gniw a htiw tuo hcaer I
.moor siht ni eb ton dluow ew ,rood eht tuo reh pmud tsuj dna sgniht rehto esoht lla yas ot gniog saw I fI
*** .raom oN .reven oN :2+1 .raom on edih reven ew
".guh yldneirf yllamron naht erom A"
.ti pleh dluoc eh fi
.esu ot yaw on dna
,ylimaf reh dna reh rof hguone egral ecnediser a fo reffo na tneilc reh nevig tsuj sah ohw reciffo gnisuoh licnuoc a
.neht kcab sreh rednu em nekat dah ehs
,wonk uoy ,yrots elttil elohw siht otni ti denrut d'I
.ereh ni su gnittup er'uoy noitisop tluciffid yllaer a s'tI
.noitpo lanif eht reh gnireffo reciffo eht dna
.reganam a rof nevar a dna sgod evif ,stac ruof ,sworc eerht sah edis sihT
",etummoc taht od nac I yaw on s'ereht wonk uoY"
.ti esufer ot reh rof elbanosaer wohemos si ti skniht ehs yhw em llet ot tuoba si ehs dna
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.won gniyas eb dluohs I tahw llew lluf wonk I ,elbat taht ssorca esle ydobyna neeb ti dah
erom ecno retlaf dna
.tib elttil a tsuj gnippalf morf flesym pots ot yleritne gniliaf ,yas I ",tuB"
.sffins dna ,dnah eno htiw drawrof rae na sbur ehS
tol taht htiw tuoba turts rethguad sih tel ot gniog ton saw eH
.taorht ym ni gnirettuts morf ti peek ot gniyrt ,htaerb wols
,esrev a ni retlaf ot gnitrats erew uoy nehw pu kcip tub
.gnihtyreve neeb dah gnos esohw elpoep owt neewteB
nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
.ot desoppus era snoegip yaw eht ,tsoor eht ni hcrep ym pu nekat dna ,kcab emoc dah I
.tew yawa semoc wap reh dna
.dab taht ton si yllaer
niatrec ylbanosaer flesym dnif I
.ylrednet dna ylwols
.sraey wef a rof erehwyna og ot evah ton lliw yeht tsael ta
,selur eht edisni krow ot evah ll'eW
"?wonk uoy ,uoy t'nsaw ti hsiw tsuj I"
.eliforp sdaeRdooG rieht no
.gnihcraes evitcaorp fo dnik taht od ot ylekilnu si noitseuq ni reciffo eht taht
,syas ehs "?ko uoY"
.meht rof cisum dnuof ohw sdneirf reh fo eno neeb dah tI
,riniel tsuj ro
.llaf ecaf reh ees dna
ti os ,hguoht ,gnivil lanummoc htiw
,ylimaf eno tsuj er'yehT
niaga hctiwt sreksihw reH
.tuo uoy tros nac eW
eciov tcaf fo rettam eht ni yas I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.emit a ta eno ,ereh kcab thgir pu dne ll'yeht dna ,sdneirf rieht fo lla morf yawa netfo tsom ,sraey owt ni seilimaf tnereffid eerht htiw yats d'yeht ylnommoC
.su fo edis rehtie no selcibuc fo wor eht gnitacidni ,smra derruf-nworb
.ytinrete rof pu flesruoy tes ot deen uoy gnihtyreve uoy gnivig llits s'eh tub ,seno doog eht fo yna rof ti gniod s'eh
revo dellorts tub
.gniyrt ma ,tsael ta ,I taht tsurt neht dna
.ti dnif pleh ot desoppus si licnuoc eht nehw yllaicepse ,ni evil ot ecaps evah ton dna
:1 pool murd tliub motsuc dedda htiw anaruB animraC s'ffrO lraC morf spilC :kcart gnikcaB
lla ta star on dna
.esac eht gniganam enoemos yb tuo gud eb ot evah dluow enildaed ehT
srebmun eht esuaceb
srehtaef yerg delttom fo elip a no
.ti fo edis rehto eht no tar eht ta ssalg ytiruces eht hguorht gnikool dna
.gum eht nwod stup ehs dna
,eralg yleets reh fo taeh eht si
,ekoj yllis fo dnik a ekiL
.ytilibats htiw ffo retteb syawla ylraen yrev era nerdlihc taht yas
.ysae t'nsi ni er'yeht elicimod derahs eht ekil gnisuoh yraropmet ,oN
.tcatnoc eye gnikaerb reven dna
.noitcaer taht evomer nac gniniart fo tnuoma on taht gniwonk tub
.elbat eht no reh erofeb smra reh gnissorc ,drawrof snael dna shgis ehS ".dah
"?haey ,rehto hcae was ew tsal rebmemer ot gniyrt er'uoY
.eciohc elbisnes eht saw ti em dlot
.drawrof snael dna gum reh nwod stup aralC .drawer a tahW
.noegip yllis emos tsuj si esac elbissopmi ylraelc eht htiw depmul neeb evah ot desoppus nosrep eht nehw ton yllaicepsE
,rettam ton ot ti decrof I
.esu reh draeh reve dah I enot tsetfos eht ni em ot dias dah aralC ",yawa lla ti
.eeffoc reh fo pis a sekat ehs dna
,yrgna naht das erom hcum sdnuos taht eciov a nI
,egassem a reh evig ot desoppus noegip a m'I
,htiw gnah ot detnaw ehs tnedor yna dekcip evah dluoc ohw
.wonk ot deen uoy gnihtyreve syas sdik evah yeht nehw sneppah tahw ot seilppa rettil mret eht taht tcaf eht tsuJ
...elttil a tiaw ,wonk uoy ,ot evah tsuj ll'tI
.kaeb ym revo gniw ym fo hsurb evitcnitsni raen a pots ot flesym niartser ot evah dna yas I ",guh A"
gnihctiwt sreksihw
.taht ekil esac a hguorht yaw rieht gid ot
,flesym eno ekat ot drawrof nael I sA
.oga sraey evif ytnewt htiw dnuora gnah ot desu I dik eht ekil gnihton skool nosnhoJ aralC
flesym nworht dna
",nosnhoJ ssiM ,yleruS"
.liaf ot meht ekil elpoep ecrof ot ,em ekil elpoep yb dengised metsys A
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
;ma I ereH .htaerb wols
.niaga ydaer ti dah uoy nehw pu ti kcip uoy tel neht dna
.tnemom eht ta elbaliava noitadommocca fo tol a ton tsuj si ereht
,hcum oot pu gnifoop morf srehtaef kcen ym peek ot gniyrt ,yas I "?nodraP"
.od ot em ekil dluow yeht tahw od ot elbaliava secruoser hguone t'nera ereht
.sneppah siht emit yreve od I ekil leef I ,ecnelis eht nI
.stneilc yrgna yrev
,skced fo riap a fo dloh a tog dah meht fo eno tub
,ti ta sffins dna
”taR gniylF“:yojne esaelP
doohdlihc ruo morf esingocer ton od I ssenitniad a
,daeh ym ni niaga gniteem su fo aedi elohw eht nur ev'I
.ffo srepat ehS "...ot
.erac otni spup eht ekat ot eb dluow licnuoc eht rof esruoc lagel ylno eht dna
,ecnis nees ev'I sgniht tsrow eht fo eno si tI
.sreylf eht nees ev'I ?loohcs taht dnA
.ti rof dedrawer neeb dah I
.ytterp eb ton lliw ti
,hahcaet ruoy eb ot pu thgir pets eW
.snevar eht fo eno tsniaga eciov reh esiar ot gnirad rof ydoolb dekcep neeb dah ehs retfa airetefac s'loohcs eht fo renroc eht ni snib eht dniheb gnirewoc noegip eht depleh dna
.em rof nesohc eb ot dewolla dah I eman eht saw ruls taht nehw kcaB
.hguone llew kool taht rebmemer I"
.htiw sdrow ym dna cisum ym erahs dluoc I ydoboN
”taR gniylF“ saw sihT
,reh derewsna ton dah I
.reh erofeb elbat eht no rehtaef eht nwod stup yltneg dna syas ehs ",wonk I ,wonk I"
,dlaraH morf trapa tub ,yrros m'I"
,ydeew reh sdaerps dna ,seunitnoc ehs
.reve sbulc cisum ssalc retfa gnizama tsoM
.yas selur eht tahw wonk uoy dna
.cigol ekil tlef ton dah ti tub
,ti sdeen taht ydobyreve emoher ot secruoser eht evah t'nseod licnuoc eht yaw emas eht dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
",si tnecs ruoy doog woh nettogrof d'I"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.kcats eno hguorht kcilf dna nolat a htiw pu hcaer
,htooteulB JD .taef dratsaB yppalF dna swalC raelC yb ")xim
.sisylana dna scitsitats noitalupoP
.repap fo eceip taht otni ti gnillitsid dna
gnivael ,sdrow eht pu derevoc yllanif dah dias dah ehs tahw fo hturt eht gnisiugsid layarteb fo gnileef eht ,ailartsuA ot yenruoj eht gnirud tub ,htuoy fo erif eht neeb dah tI
.em rof yrros sleef ehs ekil kool ti ekam taht seye htiw dna
,ni pu ti parw ot dnif ot elba neeb evah I epat der eht lla ni tsol yltneinevnoc esac rieht dna ,noitadommocca yraropmet ni spup rieht dna dlaraH ,aralC htiw tuB
htiw gum reh pu skcip ehS
.yawa enog dah cisum ehT
dnuof seigolohtna eht ni seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy
.mraerof reh htiw tuons reh gnibbur retfa seunitnoc ehs
,gnisuoh elbatius oN
era snoegip sa doog sa tuoba era staR
,doof suoiciled yllausu gnikooc neewteb emit rieht tilps yeht erehw ,sdnaldiM hsilgnE eht ni gnixaler dnuof eb yllausu nac ohw
,devirra I nehw tub ,raf taht ylf ot skeew em koot tI
sdrow ruo rof cisum eht su nevig dah ohw nam eht taht esnes lufituaeb ,lufrednow ,esnes edam tI
,gnisuoher htiw od ot gnihton evah ot gniog peek I sgniteem esoht taht tuo dnif reve ot erew seugaelloc ym fo yna fI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dah dah ew tahw dna reh fo em dednimer ti esuaceb ,neht litnu efil derahs ruo neeb dah taht cisum eht dedracsiD
.rehto eht no ruoF .edis siht no
.kcab si cisum eht tsael ta ...tsael ta tuB
".ynohpmys ruo ot kcab thgir teg tsuj d'ew ,llew ,dna sniarG eulaV fo gab emas eht rof barg htob ,otseC ni nwod ni teem d'ew
.evol t'nsaw neht kcab dah dah ew tahW
,sdrow eht hctam ton seod eciov ehT
secruoser eht evah t'nseod osla licnuoc eht
,thgir saw ehs wenk I
.sraey ruof txen eht rof efil ym dellif srebmuN
,hguoht ,kaeps I sa leef od I tahW
.reffo rehtona tcejer yeht fi
.kcab gnimoc eb t'now uoy sruoy fo dneirf tnedor taht llet" ot em dlot dna ,ailartsuA ni loohcs wen a htiw pu em tes dah rehtaf yM
.dah gnihtyreve hguone raeN
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb ”taR gniylF“
.od ot elba eb reve ll'I naht erom s'tI
,t'nseod ylurt ti hcihw
noitcive fo regnad ni tnanet gnisuoh licnuoc a eb ot desoppus era eW
sgniw ym fo noitisop eht gnitsujda erofeb stnemom wef a tiaw I
PE laiceps duolCcisuM( eroM revE reveN" morf tprecxE
,secnatsmucric eht nevig neve
.aet ym fo pis a ekat ot drawrof nael yletarebiled dna ,yas I ",haeY"
,yawa selim derdnuh wef a erew yeht ton ro rehtehw
".taht wonk I dna ,od ot boj a tog uoY
.yerg krad nwo ym tsniaga egamulp etihw
,gninaem lla gnisol dna dnuora gninnips tsuj sdrow s'aralC htiw ,daeh nwo ym ni emit hcum os tneps dah I
swalC raelC ecaf reksihw dekciw tsom eht htiw dratsaB yppalF relur latot ruoy si sihT