:debircsed eh deen taht saw deniamer taht llA
sdog rehto eht dna eh
,drow ym ni eveileb ohw srewolloF ot nevig si hcuS
.nruter yllautneve dluow I wenk I ,nwod peeD
;won gnorw em teg t’noD“ .dnah ym devaw I
.waj renni eritne ym derevoc yllacitcarp ti…eugnot tahT
,noitcere deerf ehT
”?deneppah tahW-W“
.noitanigami suorutnevda ym fo tnemgif decudni-maerd a tsuj saw eh taht ’sibunA‘ llet ot ,mih tpurretni ot em detnaw ytilanoitar deulav syawla taht niarb ym fo edis nrobbuts ehT
”.em rof tliub yeht elpmet eht fo edisni gnikaens uoy dnuof I yhw dna ,enummoc ’srewolloF ym ni ereh gniod era uoy tahw
,sicoV sumoD yb
,em tih yllanif ti nehw denediw yllacimoc seye yM  ”.tsae
fi…ytinrete lla rof siht od ot detpmet neeb ev’dluow I ,ytsenoh lla nI
”.ni er’uoy eno eht ekil hcum retpahc dnoces a gnimrof adaveN ni won si eh ,kaeps ew sA
”!hfm ,detnelat era uoy ,hooO“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.seot gnilggiw ym tsniaga esraoc tlef teprac loow eht yaw eht ot retsalp egieb s’gniliec eht ni kcarc eht morf ,nwod sliated fo tseinit eht nettog dah eh—sibunA ,rehtar ro—doG
.htgnel s’mra ta em morf ecnatsid sih gnipeek ylesiw
.ylleb reeb thgils a em gnivig ylbaton
.tnemtrapa epacsdnim ym nihtiw dna elpmet eht ni kcab ,hcti ym dehctarcs eh yaw eht fo em dednimer ti debircsed yleugav eh yaw ehT
.ecaf dnuor sih no elims decrof eht edih ot elttil did feiler tnetnoc ehT
.em ot pu gnimraw TON saw taht rennam ysetuc a ni niaga daeh sih gnitlit ylyoc
.retal setunim tneve niam eht rof t’nerew ti
.uoy rof melborp a eb ton lliw ti taht wonk I ,smaerd ruoy nihtiw eb lliw ti hguohtlA
,psarg rednet a htiw teluma hknA eht gnidloh elihw delims yltfos I
,sevael ybur htiw derettil sklawedis dehsilop eht
,em ta nwod derats dna kcab sih dniheb smra sih decalp eH
tslihw wap a gnisiar ,em detpurretni lakcaj eht ”,flesruoy mlac
,’erutaerc‘ ro nomed on ma I uoy erussa em tel ,ma I ohw gnidrager noitseuq ruoy rof sA“  .tsud otni kcab dehsinav sisao eritne eht sa tsuj ,erutaerc eht ot kcab dekrej daeh yM
,sroreuqnoc cidroN eht ot rirneF
.nagro regnol sih tsniaga dekcil hcihw
,hgiht renni sih tsniaga dekael enim sa hcamots rewol ym tsniaga gnibborht dna toh
”?eman ym wonk uoy od woH“
.yned ro ekuber ot derehtob rehtien I hcihw ,gniyl fo em desucca nus ehT
.ekas s’trofmoc rof ti dloh dna teknirt eht rof hcaeR
.notrebmiK ni devirra uoy ecnis reve uoy gnihctaw neeb evah I“
.tsae eht ot seitic tnereffid owt ni
,dekrans ylthgil I
,tsaE elddiM eht ni ytinaitsirhC fo esir eht sulp ,eman rieht ni sreyarp ro srewollof detoved tuohtiW
.thgirf morf drawkcab delbmuts ylraen I ,ytisnetni hcus htiw noitcerid ym ni sworb sih gniworruf ,ffo mih kcit ot demees msacras yM
eseht piks nac uoy
.elbiB eht fo naf gib a neeb reven ev’I
esab eht raen seglub ralubolg owt gnivah dna
.latrom raed ,ti morf raF
,htgnel ni toof a tsomla dna nac reeb a naht rekciht doots rebmem der gnikael s’lakcaj eht ,kcoc nwo ym ot detsartnoC
seitirohtua eht fi neppah lliw tahw fo raef tnatsnoc ni evil uoy tub ,sllaw eseht nihtiw srewolloF ym fo emos sa ylhsrah sa toN
,dloc a ot esolc gnihtyna thguac uoy erofeb sroodni uoy yrrac dluow srehto eht dna eH
.em dniheb detarbiv elkcuhc gnimoob a
!kcA“  .eenk dna sdnah ym htiw
.em revo hsarc ezeerb looc a dna sregnif dexaler ym elkcit dnas gnileef
,)tsaf os deb ykaerc eht otni kcuf ot ton revo dna revo flesym gnillet ,lleh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.meht llac uoy eveileb I ,’gnivigsknahT‘ dna
,em derehtob taht noitseuq a ot deladepkcab I  ”…edapS nhoJ
.ereh yug lanoitar a m’I tub ,ti morf raF
,thgir ym ot retaw fo loop llams a deciton I nehw yllaicepse
”…llacer I taht won ,uoy sa noitcaer emas eht gnivah tsomla
,deunitnoc neht ,erom ecno delkcuhc lakcaj ehT
.drager hgih ni soobat ciahcra hcus dloh ton od eW“
,tiaW ?em htiw tnaw uoy od tahW ?uoy era ohW“
.hgiht renni ym tsniaga drawpu hsurb kcoc ym tlef I sa spil ym hcaer ot deliaf sdrow tub ,tsetorp ot deirt I ”…eht tahW
tahT…saw…tahT“ ,depsar I ”…tahT“  .erutpar lufssilb ni ereht yal I sa ecaf ym dehcnerd taewS
.klawedis emas eht no em yb dessap ohw stnediser eht htiw gnitcaretni yllanoisacco
”.sbmob cimota ehT“
”…ecarg ruoy ni m’I taht sehsiw eH .gniyarp s’eH“
,teef ym ot gnilbmutS
.dnah tfel ym ni ecalkcen hknA eht dleh llits I ,tekcop rehto ym ni yek eht rof gnihsiF
”,gninrom worromot ytic ruoy rof evael uoy erofeb ,ekat ot uoy rof noitisoporp eno evah I ,ecA ,yaw eht yB“
.worbeye na desiar I
.did sibunA ekil bojwolb a em nevig reve dah
,daeh ym fo gninoitisop thgir eht htiw tub ,tsrif ta drawkwa erom ssik eht edam elzzum regnol siH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,flesruoy mlaC“  ”—daed I ma…I ma
,raey siht tsevrah eht fo dne eht etarbelec ot si tI
.ksa ot dedeen neve eh ekiL
”?mret eht si kniht I ,’ytrap rebmuls‘ a
,lliswodniw evisserpmi s’yrekab eht ni gnikab eip nikpmup a
.ytilitref fo lautir a ni gnikatrap eb lliw su fo lla epacsdnim derahs ym nihtiW“
.llew sa ralucatceps saw ydob s’dog ehT
.lakcaJ eht esiarP .sibunA esiarP
.tahwemos demlac sibunA ,yllufknahT
,derepmihw I ”…laer t’nsi siht…si siht tuB-B“  ”.erawanu
.noos yrev evirra dluow retniw delangis taht ezeerb gnillihc eht morf sevlesmeht tcetorp ot ylesolc stekcaj rieht gniraew ,seirecorg eht rof yaw rieht edam snailivic wef A
,ecalkcen eht dna stelecarb eht
.nam-flah/lakcaj-flah eht
.8102 ni
.saw ecno I ,tsael
.taorht ffurg ym fo kcab eht morf delbbub rethgual desumA
.retpecs ycnaf sih yrrac t’ndid tub
,ymrA eht ni saw I ecnis delesihc ro delcsum sa ti saw regnol oN
.sreveilebnon fo sevil eht delur evah ainam suoethgir dna aionarap hcum woh gnisuma etiuq ti dnif I“
,noitasucca eht ta deralf slirtson yM
,nihc ym derewol rehto eht elihw
.elat sih em llet lakcaj emosdnah sih ot denetsil I sa dnim ym fo kcab eht otni dedecer ylwols ti ,revewoH
”,elbatrofmoc…erom leef uoy ekam dluow yrenecs eht fo egnahc a thguoht I“
.nwod gnihsarc emac tuo dessap I erofeb morf seiromem eht fo lla
.em fo lortnoc ni saw sibunA .desrever saw elor ym ,hguoht woN
.edisni uoy dnuof eh nehw demrah eb ot ton erew uoy taht ,nemsdraug eht fo eno ,nosrednuG etaN demrofni I“
.lortnoc ekat nam regnorts rehtona gnittel yllanif saw tuoba erac I lla
.edapS nhoJ ,daed ton era uoy ,oN“
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer
,guh rednet a otni em desserac smra gnorts sih nehw ,lamirp erom emaceb slrans detartnecnoc sih nehw devirra xamilc ruo ,sibunA fo esac eht nI
”…emit a nopu ecno ,tsixe did tpygE fo sdog eht taht eurt si tI“  .no dna no
.llew sa detanimircsid dna detucesrep era uoY“
”—irhC suseJ-J…doG hO“
,sgel sih otno depsarg sdnah ym fo eno sa gnitnap ’sibunA gniraeh ni tsol flesym dnuof I
,dlrowrednu eht ot setag eht dedraug ohw surebreC sa ,otulP sa
.elims tnedifnoc sih no gnirevaw sa hcum os reven eninac ralucsum eht
,deksa yllanif I ”…oS“
.ylsuorogiv don saw od dluoc I lla litnu ,yliratnemom derevaw eciov yM ”…I“
)!yxes TON si eh( ralucsum ,gnitadimitni eht taht
.stcetihcra rieht fo sdnim eht nihtiw denigami neve erew selpmet taerg eht erofeb ro won ton
.shtaerb trohs neewteb detnap sibunA ”,heH“  ”…yloh…loh…hu.…hooO“ ,loord lacisnesnon otni sdrow ym gnirruls
.ytilauxes neddih sih fo syoj eht gnirevocsid yob deganeet drawkwa na ekil erom dna nam gnihtemos-ytriht a ekil ssel gnileef
”.emitemos niaga tisiv ot ediced uoy epoh I dna ,edapS .rM ,egalliv elttil ruo ot gnimoc rof uoy knahT
,dnah ym ekahs ot pu doots dna kcab riahc sih dehsup lliH royaM
”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“ levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
”…skeehc ssa yb neewteb gnitteg dnas toh emos si deen I gniht tsaL“
,roirp sruoh ruof-ytnewt gnihtyna ni htiaf on ot elttil dah gnivah etipseD
?ti dneherpmoc eh lliw woH
.wolgretfa ruo ni dewols ti sa tsehc ym pota gnitser wap thgir sih
.derewsna eh ”…enummoC eht fo edistuo seno devol rieht htiw tcatnoc ni peek ot dewolla era yeht ,on hO“
.dnegel dna htym ngierof eb ot demussa syawla d’I hcihw gnihtemos fo ecneserp eht ni saw I fi nevE
”…hself elam eht derreferp uoy denrael reve
?gniod eh saw tahW
,dees enivid sih gnikael llits rebmem sih
.htrib ecnis mih nopu decalp yteicos namuh taht selkcahs eht morf flesmih eerf ot deen eht tlef nilknarF
”?tluc a mrof ot dediced uoy…oS“
.efil ym fo dne eht rof em htiw niamer dluow taht
,tsrif ta kcaba nekat saw I
.hcuot ylnam sih ta gnilbmert
”.uoy rof wohs a mrofrep ot meht dlot I esuaceb tub
.moordeb a ni won erew ew :esle gnihtemos deciton yllanif I ,hguoht ssik ylnevah eht morf yawa gnilluP  .htaeD fo doG
”.edapS nhoJ ,tlef eb nac serusaelp fo tsetaerg eht ,smaerd ni nevE“
.dekan yletelpmoc saw I taht ezilaer ylneddus em edam dniw fo tsug a ,esle gnihtyna dneherpmoc ro yas neve dluoc I erofeB
yrots s’yadoT  .trAtnaiveD ro
.tekcop taoc hcnert ym edisni ti hcaer dna dnah tfel ym ekat ot detpmet gnileef tsomla
,artapoelC ,hoarahP tsal eht fo htaed eht gniwollof ,taht em ot denialpxe sibunA
?’emosdnah‘ sa mih fo kniht I did yhw ,doG(
”?srewolloF eht tuoba ffirehS eht ro em ot troper ot lanimirc gnihtoN“
,emulov neve na ni ekops eh
sA…royaM .rM ,’lanimirc‘ sa elcric a ni sgnos gnignis ,sporc gnitnalp dna gniworg seippih odriew emos tnuoc uoy sselnu toN“
”?…ro“ ,ecnelis fo tnemom a retfa deksa I ”,evael ot dewolla elpoep era…oS“
.taebtraeh ythgim a ekiL
,tliuq egral a ni depparw flesym ees dluoc I ,retaw s’loop eht fo selppir gnihtoos eht nihtiw ,hguone eruS
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
”.noos os edisni rotagitsevni na dnes ot meht tcepxe ton did I tub…ytsenoh lla ni
,mih ees ot denrut yllacitamotua ydob yM
.tsal eht eb ton lliw uoy dna ,em fo lla gnippihsrow ni elggurts ot latrom tsrif eht ton era uoY“
.lluks ym fo tnorf eht ta deniamer cigol revetahw htiw deraeppasid tlef I snoitibihni revetahW ”.od I“
.sreyarp fo nruter a esnes dluoc yeht litnu peels ot dediced tser ehT
,tsrif ta deneppah tahw gnirednow ereht yal I sA
,flesmih esopmoc ot redro ni hcamots sih ot wap a decalp dna dehgual sibunA ,taht htiW
.gninrom hcae edamnu dekool syawla deb ym yaw eht nevE
roirp thgin eht no decsinimer I sa sniol ym ni yllaicepse dna tsehc ym ni ti leef dluoc I ,hguoht evol siH
.naidisbo tfos morf devrac eutats a ekil ,noitcefrep ot delesihC
”.flesruoy eb ot elba eb lliw uoY .smra nepo htiw uoy emoclew lliw ew ,enummoC eht ta su nioj ot tnaw uoy dluohS“
,eninimef ro enilucsam ,latrom yeht eb ,tem ylteercsid reve I nam oN  ”.edapS nhoJ
?llew sa noitarbelec siht gnidnetta ni detseretni eb uoy dluoW
?oga shtnom reciffo ecilop dekoops a fo yromem eht depiw yldalg ohw ytied tneicna eht syaS“
.erawanu ma I kniht uoy nehw ydob ym revo rednaw seye ruoy leef nac I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
.denodnaba ecnis gnol efilretfa na ot meht ekat dluow eh os evirra ot sluos rof gnitiaw ,sibunA erew meht gnomA
.niaga morf draeh eb ot reven ,nwo ruo dnoyeb seno rehto revocsider dna smlaer htob evael ot esohc sdog rehtO
,demmuh eh ”,hguone riaF“
”?eurt gnikcuf lla s’tI
.tsif depsalc a ni tsehc erab sih ot wap thgir sih gnicalp lakcaj eht ,em ot kcab gnicnalg
.rebmem eninac sih pu gnirehtal yllacigam dehsinif gnivah ,em ot dnammoc eht derepsihw sibunA
,nisnocsiW larur ni desab
”lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF“   yojne esaelP
.dias ylpmis lakcaj eht
.eromyna tsixe neve ot nosaer on dah yeht tlef meht fo tsom
tluc desoppus a etagitsevni ot tnes eye etavirp s’0591 a ,edapS nhoJ ,emit tsaL
)…lamina-trap saw eH
”—gniklat er’uoy-y tahw wonk t’nod I“
,erutpircs yloh rieht fo daer ev’I tahw morF
,retal setunim ydob ym revo dellor eH
.eb ot detnaw su fo hcae sa lacov sa eb dluoc ew ,teiuq sevlesruo peek ot dedeen I dna rentrap ym erehw spukooh suoiverp ekilnU
.nooM tsevraH eht fo lavitseF eht dellac stros fo ytivitsef…a dloh ot elpmeT eht ni rehtegot gnirehtag era lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF eht ni tluda yreve tsomla ,thgindim ta thginoT“
,enim dekop yllanoisacco eson kcalb tew siH
.mlap ym ni edih ot hguone llams ssorc leets dloc a
.em ta dekniw eh sa elzzum sih fo edis eno gnikcil ,niaga dennirg sibunA ”,nam rehtona fo hself eht leef ot erised tsuj uoy nehw yltsedom os sserd uoy ,lla retfA
.su dnuora detuorps ylneddus sehsub tiurf citoxe dna seert mlap fo gnitsisnoc sisao neerg dna dnarg A  ”…tcaf nI
?yllaer ,ereh em gnirb uoy did yhw“
”?elpmet eht ni kcab ekawa saw I nehw rO
em morf ezilacov ot erusaelp fo slwoh dna snaorg dna snaom ym dewolla I
.detcepxe I ekil gnihton erew spil ’sibunA
.enips ym pu revihs mraw a gnidnes llits eciov yklis tey enotirab sih
.tseretni htiw deddon I ”,si tI“
”?tnemnorivne railimaf a ni dexaler erom leeF“
.seot ruo rednu htrae ydnas eht ot elbmut ti draeh ylerab I
.sibunA morf deticile I naorg hcae htiw hcamots ym gnilkcit yllacitsaisuhtne liat eht ,shgiht yrruf sih neewteb rebmem sih gnippihsrow saw I taht os selor ruo dehctiws I ,tniop emos tA
.sih fo htolcniol taht netsafnu ot swap sih fo eno derewol sibunA
.yawyna ot dedeen I taht toN
”.evitcartta em dnif uoy taht wonk eno rof I ecnis ,fo demahsa eb ot gnihton si tI
”?neht no gniog eb lliw tahW“
.seye esnetni sih morf ylthgirb gnitcelfer ,ecafrus gnimlac eht sdrawot )?wap(
,yks thgin raelc a ot seye ym denepo I
”,eussi detacilpmoc a saw tI“
.yleerf evil dna yleerf evol ot detnaw dlaregztiF nilknarF
’samtsirhC‘ .dlrow eht fo noiger siht ni detarbelec era taht syadiloh eht gnirud sevitaler tisiv ot evol ,os od ot erised yeht fi ,srewolloF ym fo ytnelP“
.dnegel dna htym tub gnihtyna si ytied rieht taht derevocsid sah
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer  eb lliw
.edapS nhoJ ,lufhsab eb ot deen on si erehT“
”.dnetta ot tnaw I ssa yloh ruoy teb uoY“ ,ytied lakcaj tneicna eht dlot I dna ,ecaf ym no deraeppa nirg luftsul A
’namuh‘…tsom eht gnoma era uoY
.htimS niatnuoM eht
htaehs eninac a morf gnidurtorp
flesym gnirevoc deirt I sa kcohs ym ot hcum ,deniamer em no gnihtolc fo hctits a toN
,em ediseb delkcuhc sibunA
”.draug doots yeht sa nilknarF dna lamaJ no gnirueyov ,gnineve siht reilrae tops gnidih ruoy morf uoy dehctaw I“
,krow dluow siht taht deyarp I
,noitidepxe lacigoloeahcra na no elihw selpmet ym fo eno dnuof ohw ewoD nodgnaL sa wonk uoy nam eht saw tI“
,era uoy ohw wonk I“
,seenk detfil htiw kcab ym no deil I
.htaerb s’lakcaj eht no sbreh dekculp ylhserf dna seirrebwarts teews ,enip yekoms detsat I
.aciremA ot mih dewollof I os ,renroc yreve dnuora liomrut dna raw livic htiw ,tpygE ni yats ton dluoc eW
strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,gniffocs morf flesym pleh t’ndluoc I ,rethgual fo yrd dna deriT
,klawedis eht no em ot txen thgir doots eh ekil ekops sibunA ”,noitpeced fo evorppa ton od I ,yllamroN“
.ydnad dna enif lla s’eh ,s’ffirehS eht fo ytuped remrof eht rof
.stimil nwot s’notrebmiK ot denruter I erofeb em ot detfig srewolloF eht taht ecalkcen a ni depparw ,edisni teknirt eht desserac dna desrup sregnif yM
.rewop rieht esol ot nageb ylwols
.seert eht ni gnitooh lwo na dna knoh s’elibomsdlO na rof evas
,muesum a ot etanod ot steknirt erom dnif ylerem dluow eh deveileb nodgnaL“
”…ecA ,em htiw ehtaerB“
.draveluob nwotnwod gniltsub dna dedworcrevo s’eekuawliM ot nosirapmoc ni delap ,keew a nihtiw neewollaH rof detaroced ydaerla ,teerts niam s’notrebmiK  .em dnuora yrenecs nmutua eht ni ekat ot seohs ym morf pu dekool I ”.mmmH“
.sdnuom kcalb owt tneserp ot hcamots sih otno revo dellor ylkciuq eninac egral eht sa pley ot ylno ,mih ot pu kool ot ’pihsrow‘ ym desuap I
.yldednahffo dekoj I ”,aedi dooG“
.ecneserp ruo ta gnilppir yltneg
”…ecalp siht ni uoy ot kaeps I sa uoy revo hctaw neht
,eekuawliM ni efil a tog I
?tresed a fo elddim eht ni I saw yhW
.eekuawliM ni kcab moordeb s’tnemtrapa YM ,rehtar rO
,sedapS fo ecA eht ni sa ,ecA .eheH“ .dekrow tI
noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif osla nac uoY
.emoc ot sthgin ralimis ynam rof epoh sa llew sA
,htolcniol nedlog taht erow llits eH
”.suoicipsus eb dluow YDOBON esruoc fo ,haeY
.sgnidnuorrus ym deyevrus I
.erew yllaer uoy ohw ro ,erew yllaer uoy tahw wonk tuohtiw elims a uoy gniviG
.mlac dna gnidnats yats ot deganam I tey ,elbbow seenk ym gnikam ylraen ,elzzum derruf-krad sih ssorca ylthgirb delims eH
,sibunA sa hcus nemiceps enif a morf yllaicepsE
”.em ni eveileb ton od uoY“
”.edih ot gnihtyna tog lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF eht kniht t’nod I
.em fo pot no despalloc lakcaj egral eht litnu stsehc ruo revo lla gnitalucaje yb tius dewollof I
,erutarepmet edistuo eht ot eud dloc yllaitini hguohT
”.yaw rehtie rewolloF yraronoH na flesruoy redisnoc tub“
.democlew yltaerg tub ,erofeb decneirepxe reven I ecap fo egnahc a saw tI
.ylthgit ti dleh I sa srae ym otni detanoser eciov peed dna railimaf A
”,gnivil eht neve semitemos dna ,daed eht fo sluos eht egduj ot desu ohw dog a ma I“
,rehtar ro ,hself elam rof deen eht
.eson ym fo egdirb eht gnikcil tslihw nepo gnir ym dehcterts lakcaj eht
***  ”.wonk I .ecA ,wonk I“
,haN…fael wen a revo nrut ot detnaw tsuj eh demees ti ,dessentiw I tahw morf tub ,thgiew emos tsol dna riah emos werG
.taht ekil gnihtemos od ot naht retteb wenk I ,revewoH
;nwot llams yna ot nevig saw taht ssentniauq eht ni rof pu edam ti ,ytisrevid ro spohs fo yteirav ni dekcal ti tahw ,revewoH
,rehtruf deriuqni I
.kcen sih dnuora ecalkcen hknA eht gnisserac llits dnah eno ,em dna ti neewteb gnicnalg yllanoisacco elihw oidar eht ot gninetsil saw denoitnem lakcaj
.yawa dekcil neht eh hcihw ,seye gnicniw ym fo srenroc eht ni demrof sraeT
,spil ym tsniaga tfos tey thgit
.niaga dlob gnileef ylneddus ,dekramer I
.emit fo dne eht rof tiaw dna efilretfa eht ni yats ot esohc sdog emoS
.ssik s’lakcaj eht otni detlem I sa pih ym tsniaga deggaw taht liat A
,skcottub ym tsniaga spih sih gnillor ylwols retfA .did eH
.nisnocsiW ,notrebmiK ni thgin ,lanif eht reven tub ,tsal ym no smaerd )yxes dna(
,edisni tnew I erofeb em ot ekops sibunA
.htgnel ym no delbbin dna ,dekcus ,desserac ,dekcil lakcaj eht woh ot derapmoc gnihton saw ymmoT fo htuom tevlev ehT
”?tca na hcus ni
I…tsehc gnitaews ym tsniaga ylesolc tpews selppin trep dna selcsum detplucs sih ,niks yriah ym tsniaga dehsurb ruf krad hcir sih yaw eht ,kcoc citsilamina sih fo mia eht htiw denibmoc tahT
”…tub-tub ,ma I ebyam…I“
,em dednimer dog lakcaj eht
,deddon sibunA
.em rof regnuh uoy wonk I
,aes eht ssorca elihw sibunA em deman tpygE fo snoitazilivic taerg ehT
”.edisni emit sih fo seiromem sih epiw ot dedeen I
”,dnim ruoy ni sa em ebircsed uoy revetahw ro
,eciwt…retal shtnom niaga deneppah ti ,nehT
”.yloh si ti ,deednI“
.’sdeF eht dna doG ythgiM ruo fo htarw
.yob riohc duol a ekil
,enim ot elzzum sih etivni mih hctaw ot dog eht ta pu gnirats ,ezag ylnevaeh sih ni tsoL
.ton did rentrap siH
.detcurtsni sa niaga tuo dna ni neht
,rof dnats lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF eht tahw dna ,ecnetsixe ym fo sevlesmeht rof derevocsid rentrap krow sih dna nilknarF nehW“
”!edapS nhoJ ,em tlusni ton oD“
”?mH“  ”.sruoy fo eugnot taht rof esu rehtona fo kniht nac I
”?edapS nhoJ ,ees uoy tahw noitseuq llits uoy od yhW
.odnecserc a mrof ot nageb yllanif su neewteb tsurht dna ssik dna noitasnes gnitcidda yrevE
.wam rellams ym otni erom ecno eugnot trepxe sih ekans ot dog lakcaj eht gniwolla
”.enola uoy evael ll’yeht kniht I ,teiuq yats tol uoy sa gnol oS“
,niaga tnelis denrut dlrow ehT
.ees ot dog lakcaj eht rof eenk ym fo renroc eht morf pu dekeep hcihw ,tfahs mrif ym pu dna enips ym nwod tnew revihs rehtonA
…nam teews taht ,nodgnaL raed fo em dnimer uoY
,moorssalc depmarc a edisni yad a flah gnidneps retfa erutnevda ot sekib rieht gnidir nerdlihc fo kcap tneconni eht
.sih fo seye evitanimulli esoht otni derats I sa sllab ym htaenrednu rebmem derepat sih gnicalp ylluferac dog ralucsum erom eht
.taeh gnitaidar scep dna specib yrruF
.ecalkcen eht fo og gnittel erofeb gnineve ecin a dna sknaht ym sibunA taerG gnireffo ,mih htiw hgual tub pleh t’ndluoc I
,derettum I ”?kcuf eht tahW“
,sniur eht ni mih rof gnitiaw em derevocsid eH
,detpurretni sibunA ”,edapS nhoJ ,setsat ruoy fo erawa ma I“  ”—ahW“
,noitcifnaf dab dna cisum gniws ortcele ot noitcidda na sah ohw ,sicoV sumoD yb
.tuo krow dluow siht htiaf dah I
”,kaeps ew sa uoy ot gnidnet era srewolloF yM“
.slatrom uoy yb em ot nevig seman fo rebmun etinifni na fo eno si ti tub ,ekil tsom I eman eht si sibunA“ .noom eht sdrawot noziroh krad ,tnatsid eht dna em neewteb gnikool ,yldesuma liat sih dekcilf sibunA ”,si ti
,eugnot ym otni dna taorht ym fo esab eht morf tpure ot naom devarc a gnisuac
.em fo edisni ytpme mutorcs yvaeh sih tlef I dna emit lanif eno dehsup eh ,tsal gnol ta litnu ,pots tuohtiw debborht sibunA fo kcoc ehT  ”~hhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhO“  ”~hhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhA“
,tsrif ta laiceps gnihtyna mees t’ndid tI
;dednuos ti sa yllufituaeb sa detsat dog tneicna na fo ssa ehT
.duola desum eh ”,edapS nhoJ ,detcepxe I tahw morf tnereffid…era uoY“
.retcarahc rieht no latrom wollef a gnigduj sa hcum os tuohtiw etanimircsid dna etucesrep yeht tey ,ecnatpecca dna evol sehcaerp dog rieht
.lliw ym ni eveileb ohw esoht ot gnidnatsrednu dna ssendnik fo stenet nruter ot epoh ylerem I“ .deffocs sibunA
.letom ym ot kcab klaw eht gnirud moderob gningief ,tekcop taoc hcnert ym ni dnah tfel ym gnicalp elihw kcab elims gnirorrim a dereffo I ,yad llews a—tem reven yeht regnarts etelpmoc a—em dehsiw dna em ta delims yeht sA
,noon hgih erofeb ruoh na llew gnieb ti etipsed ,ksed sih dniheb denway eh ”,neht oS“
.noitpecxe eno siht saw ,yob dnA
,emas eht did I
.thgiltops yrotasucca na ekil em no dednecsed thgilnus gninrom etal eht ,kcolb a nwod letom ym sdrawot dna seert eht tsap yaw ym gnikam ,llah nwot eht fo tuo deppets I sA
”,erutluc ruoy ni snaem ti tahw fo noisrev detsiwt a emoceb sah
.are tcnitxe na morf dog a fo daetsni
.reenoitcua citnarf tey desufnoc a fo taht ekil ,tuo gnidoolf emac snoitseuq ym
.em morf psag laruttug a ticilos ot eciwt dna ecno ti gnikorts ,wap gnorts sih ni tfahs desuora ym dleh yletaciled eh sa dehgual ylteiuq dog lakcaj eht ,esnopser nI  ”?’ecA‘“
eht‘ ,sdrow nwo sih ni ,tuoba gnirb ot desimorp dna enummoC eht evael ot deirt eH
.stsop evitcepser rieht ta deniamer yllufitud wef elbaronoh na ylnO
ro( hteet ym gnittirg ro pil rewol ym gnitib fo daetsni ,suhT
,daeh ym gnittap ,yllufyalp deooc eh ”,ecA lufhtiaf ym ,terf ton oD“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”~hhhhhhhooooohhhhhooooohhhhoooohoooO“  .erofeb decneirepxe reven d’I erusaelp fo kraps a dnes sih fo rebmem yniev ,enivid taht tlef I ,yllaniF
egludni…ot su rof hsiw uoy od ,oS“
.tey gniht ’dnal eht htiw gnivil‘ elohw eht rof pu ton m’I“
.niur enots eht fo sllah tneicna eht fo eno edisni erugif enol a yb dewollof ,weiv ni deraeppa elpmet egral a sa thgir
,sedaH sa flesym demialcorp I ,meht oT
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
”,edapS nhoJ ,ma I ohw ton si taht diarfa ma I“
.ylgnihtoos dias eh ”,edapS nhoJ ,diarfa eb ton oD“
.tbuod fo tseinit eht neve rof em deye ohw ,lliH royaM dna hctawtsirw ym neewteb decnalg yliratnemom I
.reyalp drocer nekorb a ekil htuom ym fo tuo emac sdrow ym ”...I-I-I“
”.edapS nhoJ ,tcerroC“
.regna ni trapa em raet ton did sibunA ,esirprus ym oT
.tuo dna edisni ,nwod dna pu deppal I emit hcae daeh ym fo sedis eht tsniaga dehsurb
”,edapS .rM ,uoy htiw eerga ot evah I kniht I ,lleW“  .did ti dnA
.thgif a ni reknilb doog a evig ot specib ym ni ssam elcsum hguone dah llits I ,kcap-xis a htiw tneps sthgin dna sregrub dellirg eht fo lla etipsed ,teY
,lakcaJ eht fo deerC eht
.hguoht dne na ot emac syawla sgniht taerG
dnah tfel sih detniop dna loop eht sdrawot deppets eh
,dennirg lakcaj ehT
.fles decudni-gurd ym ot dna ,smaerd ym fo tnemgif a ylerem eb ot depoh I tahw ot denosaer I
”.pleh yldalg lliw I ,sibunA taerG ,eman ruoy ni enod gnihtyna deen reve uoy fi tub
litnu seirutnec rof no tnew sihT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.rehtegot sdnah ytaem sih gnidloh elihw drawrof gninael
!lakcaJ eht dna em rof yad yppaH !gnihC-ahC .73.412$ .seye ym ot kcehc eht dleh I sa sibunA gniknaht ,flesym ot thguoht I ,os ebyaM
.purys elpam mraw ekil sregnif ym ffo deppird dna gnulc muC
,tuo neht ,ni dehtaerb I
”.serusaelp fo tsetaerg eht uoy wohs llahs I dna…ehtaerB“
?sromur yllis lareves revo yenom dna emit detsaw dna royam a erew uoy fi od uoy dluow tahw ,lla retfA
.erom rof repmihw uoy htaeneb nam emosdnah rehtona gnikam dna lortnoc ni gnieb ,xes lauxesomoh tuoba devol I tahw saw sihT
2 fo 2 traP ,sicoV sumoD yb
llac dluow uoy tahw ni rehtegot peels lliw yeht erehw
”?edapS evitceteD ,enummoC eht edisni elihw suoicipsus lla ta gnihton dnuof uoy“
.ydob ym no llot elbisiv rieht nekat dah gnikooc edamemoh dna stnaruatser ytic renni ,raW eht fo dne eht gniwolloF
”lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF“
.enim ot flesti desserp daeherof sih nehw dna
.eugnot tew ym otno kcab dehsup dna enihw ot detrats eh revenehw yldnof gnilims
.em ot ti debircsed yllacismihw eh sa ,’peels lanrete‘ eht otni llef noitacifimmuM fo doG eht neve yllautneve
,waj ym tsap nwod htgnel eritne eht teg ot deirt I sa ylideen sa tsomla ,llab sinnet a fo ezis eht hcae ,mutorcs derevoc-ruf sih deldnof sregnif yM
.snoitasnes eht fo lla ni tsol werg
teews detcepxe I ,em dniheb rood eht gnisolC
;I od rehtien dnA
.tnemyap ruoy s’erehT“
”,gnihtyreve segnahc siht esuaceB-B“
,tekcop ym ni ecalkcen eht ot derepsihw I ,thgis ni saw ydobon fi ees ot thgir dna tfel gnikooL  ”.yltaerG
”lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF“ fo
.evol esnetni hcus htiw sibunA ta pu dezag I woh dna ecaf der gnihsulb ym rof t’nerew ti fi ,erom detnaw I taht detnih spsag dna senihw gnisurohc yM
?laer…si tpygE tneicnA fo noehtnap eritne eht snaem taht neht
.rood s’moor letom ym ot emac I sa deddon I ,ylbmuH
.mih ta derats I yaw eht deciton eh nehw gnixaler erofeb ylthgils delruc liat ’sibunA  ”…tcnitxe neeb ecnis gnol sah reviR eliN tneicnA eht fo sgniK dna shoarahP fo emit eht ,yletanutrofnU
;nosaer nwonknu emos rof em rehtob t’ndid ,dekan yletelpmoc su fo htob ,lakcaj-flah/nam-flah a gnissik saw I tcaf ehT
”,hguoht sdnats llits reffo ehT“
,laer yllaer era uoy fI
.mlap ym ni htmraw llams a leef dluoc I erows I
”,fo maerd ylno slatrom taht noissap fo thgin a uoy evig lliw I dna drow eht yas nac uoy ,hsiw uoy fI“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
,rennam lausac a ni denialpxe sibunA
”.ecA ,peelsa llaf si od ot deen lliw uoy llA
.saw ti revetahw ,’tonk‘ a sa ot derrefer eh taht
.elpmet rieht gnidnuorrus sgnillewd eht fo eno eb ot demussa I tahw nihtiw hcuoc dehsinruf a no gnipeels
’nosrednuG etaN‘ ehT
?won thgir uoy ot gnikaeps fo yromem ym gnipiw uoy t’nera yhW
.semit tnecer ni tem evah I slatrom fo
.srae sih dniheb gnikeep noom eht sa thgirb sa llits dna gniwolg llits ,seye sih dellavir tsomla yehT .sgnaf etihw elbisiv htiw gninnirg ,sedis sih ot swap sih fo htob decalp sibunA
,em decnartne ylneddus mutorcs yksum sih dna liat desiar sih neewteb detser taht eloh knip ehT
”…saw
.htuom ym fo tser eht ot ssecca dog eht evig ot hguone sesnefed ym denekaew ti
,seman ynam yb enog evah I“
,ylpmi ro noitseuq toN .detats eh
.eurt si gniees era uoy tahw eveileb ton od uoY“ .detats
.dlrow eht fo edis rehto eht no rewop evitcurtsed s’dog rehtona eb ot deveileb I tahw fo kcohsretfa eht gnileef ot ekowa I nehw ,oga sraey thgie litnu“
ta…sluos tsol fo nortap gnidiug dna noitacifimmuM fo doG eht ,sibunA si sa em wonk tsom taht eno tub
.epan ym gnola sdap sih gnibbur ,tsehc tif ,yriah ym no wap a ecalp ot drawrof pets sibunA tel I ,ecneserp sih ni tahwemos gnixaleR
.sdog nwo rieht fo snoisrev eb ot em deveileb slacol eht
”?lla ta suoicipsus gnihtoN“  ”.epoN“
.kcehc a em evig neht
,snoitaterpretni tsom nI“
.moor emos evah lakcaj egral eht tel ot steehsdeb eht otno kcab detoocs I ,rehtegot gnihgual dna gnilkcuhC
.ecA ,uoy knaht tub“
,skeehc tcefrep siH
.wena flesym dliuber dna yats dluohs I taht hguoht em decnivnoc eH
,emahs a hcuS
.rehtegot gniyt flesti ecalkcen dediarb eht htiw ,rehtegot depool saw hcnarb pot sti taht tcaf eht saw trapa ti tes tahw ,revewoH
.selppin ym fo eno desaet regnif s’nam a nehw yojne ot animats hguone ,sulP
”.ecA ,srehto uoy wohs nac I tuB
”,tey tsuj reffo eht rof tog t’nac I tub ,hcum yrev uoy knahT“
,sgel ym ot yaw sih gnilwarc elihw dne raf eht no gnileenk ,noil a ekil derrup eh ”,deednI“
.emit fo doirep trohs a rof epacsdnim emas eht erahs nac ew erehw eno ,peels fo dnik laiceps a ni uoy decalp evah I
.deb eht sdrawot em gnissot yltpmorp yb rehtruf em desirprus sibunA
,troppus rof skcottub ym debbarg swap sih fo eno sa sehsup tnedifnoc sdrawot devlove stsurht suoituac siH
.sffuh sih morf elkcit skeehc ym gnikam elihw etsat ym otni gnilahni
,deunitnoc sibunA ”,slatrom fo dlrow gnignahc eht fo erawanu ,seirutnec rof demaerd I“
.snoitpecxe wef fo eno saw siht tub ,kcus ot naht dekcus eb ot derreferp netfo I  .detnap eh
.pu flesym ekaw dna yrt ot ecaf ym ni ti worht dna dnuorg eht morf dnas emos barg ot em ecnivnoc ot deirt tI
.mih raeh dluoc I
,ot detnaw yeht esuaceb tsuj ton s’ti ,taht did yeht yhw gnirednow er’uoy fI“
.redneval fo tnih teews a htiw tnegnup
.dne na ot emoc dah snoitan ruoy neewteb raw ediwdlrow dnoces eht taht won
.ecaf ym denedder hsulb peed A
.htuom ym morf delbmur tnemal gnivarc a ”…hoooO“
.)em sa etihw sa tub gnihtyna ro stsitfeL t’nerew yeht sa gnol os( sregnarts dna srobhgien ot sevaw emoselohw deulav taht spohs tink-esolc
,redluohs ym ot wap sih esor dog lakcaj eht
.erusaelp gnimocni eht did os tub ,dliub yllaudarg ot detrats niap ehT
”…esaelP .sibunA ,uoy tnaw I“ .hself elam SIH
.edapS nhoJ ,uoy ekil I“
,’tluc‘ ,drow tahT“
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.ecneirepxe ot snoitasnes fo elbarusaelp tsom eht ton si ti“
,s’etelhta na ekil htaenrednu delcsum dna ruf krad ni derevoc
.dehctaw eh sa sibunA desuma yltaerg hcihw gnihtemos