.wonk t’ndid I ,em ekil enoemos rof noitasrevnoc gnikam tuoba pu desiw eh ebyam ro
.em revo dehsaw aiglatson ,elttab a fo elddim eht ni tcnitsni lavivrus fo hsur enilanerda rehtona gnileef fo daetsni tub ,decafruser raW eht fo seiromeM
,drawrof deppets I ,ylsuoituaC
.eciov gnimoclew ,peed a ni ekops eh
,hsur...a dessessop syawla efil ytic-rennI
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.flesym ot derumrum I ”,tsael eht yas ot gnisirpruS“
”…nwot ecin a neeb syawla sah...notrebmiK“
;’efil fo yek‘ eht ro ,’hknA‘ na ti dellac snaitpygE tneicnA ehT
.raf levart ton did esion eht deveileb I hguoht ,sevael nellaf dna sdrib gniprihc fo ecneibma eht gnikaerb
,neethgie denrut yltnecer taht yob riohc a morf degnar slaudividni esehT
.sehsub yawaraf eht dniheb nees t’nsaw I erus gnikam tslihw sraluconib eht otni resolc seye ym decalp I
.em sdrawot pets lanif a gnikat elihw tnemesuma ni dehgis neht ,ylsuoretsiob dehgual ylneddus lakcaj ehT
,yllacitsaisuhtne dnA
.sehsub fo tekciht a dniheb dnuopmoc eht fo weiv a fo erom flesym gnivig sulp ,nees eb ton ot hguone raf tub sgnidliub fo puorg eht ot resolC
...demeeS rewolloF edisni hcae fo eritta eht
,thgiew emos tsol ylgnimees eh ,mrofinu s’ytuped sih fo edistuO
.ereht pu gniod er’yeht doG fo eman eht ni tahw etagitsevni ot uoy deen ew“
.sraluconib ym hguorht skcen ’srewolloF eht fo hcae no ecalkcen a eciton did I tub ,elpoep fo spuorg eht gnoma tey dlaregztiF tops t’ndluoc llits I ,yletanutrofnU
hguoht stnediser s’notrebmiK gnikoops detrats yllaer tahW
:sevlesmeht dellac noitagergnoc eht tahw derevocsid saw ti nehw roirp shtnom lareves degnahc lla taht ,revewoH  .sevlesmeht ot peek ot gnirreferp noitagergnoc eviterces eht fo etips ni ,’yldneirf ylbidercni‘ sa debircsed gnieb
.daor levarg eht fo edis eht ta deppots ew litnu nwod rac eht dewols snitraM reciffO  ”.era ew ereh
.otohp eht gninimaxe ,mih rof derewsna I ”?gniht a rebmemer t’nac uoY“  ”?neht sneppah tahw sseuG .dam enog d’eh nilknarF ecnivnoc ot ,niaga ti yrt ot pu nem ym flah gnirb I dna retal htnoM
,gnituohs eht decalper taht teiuq larutannu eht saw hguoht did tahW
,deklaw sa seye sih ni elkraps…fo dnik emos dah nilknarF
sneris tnatsid ,srac gniknoh
,saw eh ralucsum dna tliub woh erimda ot delevart seye gniveilebsid ,ediw ym
.tsul lauxesomoh rieht ni tsol oud eht yb dettops neeb ylekil evah d’I ,esiwrehtO
dlab mih edam ylraen taht riah nevahs-esolc htiw nam kcalb regnuoy a—
,tekram lacol eht ta sgnivrac doow neve dna gnihtolc
”…edapS nhoJ ,diarfa eb ton oD“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,noitcifnaf dab dna cisum gniws ortcele ot noitcidda na sah ohw ,sicoV sumoD yb
.elpmet enots depahs-dimaryp egnarts eht :tegrat tsriF
,dessap dnoces enO
dnah eno ni retpecs laiceps a fo dnik emos gnidloh ,htolcniol a ni nam llat a gnitciped eutats eznorb a ,yllacificepS
.moor enirhs eht morf emac tI
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
.rehtomdnarg rieht ot degnoleb taht telecarb dnomaid a ekil otnemem suoicerp emos rof hcraes neve ro
.retnec eht ni llih egral a fo egde eht gnilcric dna
,lliH royaM s’notrebmiK morf llac enohp eht dna yadirF tsal neewteB
.gniog teG .gniog teg tsuJ“
,derettum I ”…timmaD“
.pordraet nwod-edispu na htiw decalper saw enil pot eht tpecxe ssorc yna ekil dekool ti ,yllacisaB
,seert fo seiponac dniheb dih I sa sraluconib eht hguorht noitibihxe reilrae eht gnihctaw dna ytreporp eht gniyevrus ,sdoow eht ni gnignuoL  ”.em
.snibac gol yrots-owt eht fo yna naht regral on demees ti
.enasni meht demeed taht syaw ton hguoht ,ddo...demeeS
.wonk reven dluoc I ,thgis morf eunitnoc d’yeht ton ro rehtehW
,seenk sih ot flesmih gnirewol nilknarF dessentiw txen I litnu thgis eht ssecorp ot emit rehtruf yna em evig t’ndid yehT
.reyarp lauteprep ni gnileenk stnediser dna til seldnaC
,rorroh laitini eht dnoyeB
.tniop egatnav ym morf dekool enummoC eht
rebmem desserd ylralimis rehtona htiw denioj eH  .ssenetelpmoc
.selbategev eb ot deveileb I tahw dna nroc fo sklats nworg ,hserf yllufituaeb
.esactius ym ni srallod derdnuh-owt htiw keew txen eekuawliM ot nruter dna htiw revo ti teg dluow I
…yllaicepse ,nosnhoJ s’nam redlo emosdnah a fo ezis eht enigami d’I nehw ,sraey deganeet ym gnirud emit a ot kcab decsinimer I ,lufituaeb si taht droL raed hO
.dluoc I esle revetahw gnidnif dna enummoC eht edisni gnitteg devlovni hcihw ,hguoht od ot krow dah I
.ereh esle eno on s’erehT .yllacigol knihT
.niaga dna niaga ti gninepo deirt I sa bonk latem eht morf deppils sdnah gnitaews yM
eht etagitsevni ,skcab rieht dniheb tuo gnikaens esuops rieht fo sotohp meht edivorp dluoc I ,hsac hguone dah tneilc eht fI
enilwaj gnorts a rednu gnimrof nihc dnoces elbaton eht ro
,heH…ot…ot tiaw t’naC“
,yawhgih eht otno kcab rebbur denrub eh yaw eht ta ffocs dluow em fo traP
.tihs ro nemyegoob
.em sdrawot nwod ylthgils devruc kcen sti ,tfel eht ot detlit daeh sti ,daetsnI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
.owt ni ti gnittuc ,nilreB ni tliub eno eht lavir dluow taht sllaw reirrab ro ,eriw debrab ro ,ecnef deknil-niahc a evah t’ndid enil ytreporp ehT
,em dlot rekaB ffirehS ”,stnerap sih ot kcab dik sacuL eht gnirb ot ni tnew mloclaM rentrap sih dna eh retfa gnihtyreve tfel nilknarF“
,derob gnikool sa hcum os tuohtiw meht ot kaeps ot esuap
.tihs ro lairtserretartxe emos fo segaugnal eht ekil
.eunever fo deen etarepsed ni tsewdiM eht ni snwot ynam fo eno saw notrebmiK ,raw eht retfa taht em ot denialpxe rekaB ffirehS dna lliH royaM
,stsafkaerb elacsegral eht ot sknaht ylekil(
!tuo kcuf eht detnaw I .erac t’ndid I ,ereht kcab did gniht taht revetahW
…eulav ecaf ta nekat eb ot erew sromur eht fi ,llitS
.dessap ro tsol seno devol morf srettel
”lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF“   yojne esaelP
.dezilaer I ,sdraug erew yehT
.rehtegot srood nedoow owt eht gnidloh kcol eht deton dna ecnartne eht fo tnorf eht rof deppiz I ,kciuq dna wol gniyatS .dooG
.seenk sih ot gnippord erofeb rood eht gnikcol dna tnemtrapa ym otni gnippils
.mrofinu s’ytuped sih ni dlaregztiF nilknarF fo erutcip a gniwohs
.seye etavirp rof noitpircsed boj eht htiw emac netfo gniretne dna gnikaerB
erehT ?evom ytied rieht fo eutats eht was I yhw taht saW ?sag lacimehc emos htiw pu elpmet eritne eht llif neht ,taht od yeht diD
”lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF“
.yellav derevoc-nmutua eht otni repeed gnicnatsid ot em del retal gnikaens thguat-fles fo setuniM .enummoC eht ot resolc flesym dehcni dna nwod dehcuorc I
,yreneerg kciht dna seert esnemmi otni nrut dnalmraf eht fo lla gnieeS
.emitremmus fo tsohg eht ekil llah eht nwod ohce ot lwoh a gnisuac
.tnaived A .lauxesomoh A
.senifnoc sti nihtiw tnemevom deciton I nehw enots eht detropsnart yeht woh gnirednow detrats I
,ruf kcalb fo edam erugif gnisopmi ,llat eht ta depsag dna dnuora denrut yltpurba I
.tuo deffuns neeb dah em dniheb moor enirhs eht ni eldnac yreve fi sa ,krad werg gnihtyrevE
,mrala ni derepsihw I ”?…kcuf eht tahW“
,ni dedda lliH royaM ”,gnineppah si revetahW“
.serutluc fo egdop-egdoh dexim a ekil demees gnihtolc fo seciohc s’enummoC eht ,deednI
,doof dekculp fo steksab rekciw deirrac yeht sa yldemahsanu striks ro stnap ni desserd ekila enummoC eht fo nemow dna neM
.egdub ton did ti tub ,eldnahrood eht deppirg dnah yM
”.hcT“  ”?elbatrofmoc uoy ,oS“
.eutats eznorb a saw noitoved fo tcejbus eht
,esac truoc emos ni rotucesorp a yb meht tsniaga dleh ecnedive
spil sih no ssik a detnalp ,ecnatsissa s’rewolloF kcalb eht htiw pu flesmih depleh ,nihc sih depiw nilknarF
,thgis ym gnikcolb seert eht htiw tahw ,weiv tneced a edivorp t’ndid noitisop yM
H“ .sih fo sbro gniwolg esoht otni regnif sih morf yawa gnikool ,pu deird htuom yM
,neht
.ecnef deknil-niahc eht gnola gnildwad meht dnif ot deganam I tey
—noitanalpxe rehto on eb ot dah
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.ybraen seert eht ni gnitooh lwo emos dna flesym tub ydobon ot derumrum I ”,ssabmud ,sucoF“
.dnuorgkcab eht ni mehtna teivoS eht htiw elkcis dna remmah a gnivlovni seisatnaf terces dah
,gniliec eht sdrawot detniop srae kcalb siH
.setteragic fo notrac ym thguorb d’I hsiw em edam ti
.kcilc llams a ylno htiw dehcated ylisae kcol eht
.liava on ot ylno ,drawni ti dellup yletarepsed I
.ti pota noitazilivic namuh fo thgis eht ssim dluoc ydobon ,flesym delaecnoc I erehw morf nevE
.seert enipla ot tlahpsa derreferp syawla I  2 fo
,elpoep dlo dna seilimaf fo lluf ,egatniv
,relbmut eht rof dnuora gnilffuhs dna tekcop taoc hcnert ym morf tik gnikcipkcol ym tuo gnillup retfa ,em rof ylikcuL
.sdoow eht otni repeed lortap rieht ot denruter dna
,detrats ecnallievrus ym tnemom eht morf ,yllacisaB
”.seippih emos tsuj er’yehT
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.droffa dluoc reveohw ot ffo dnal s’nwot fo emos lles ot hguone etarepsed gnitteg royam suoiverp eht ni detluser thguord ytsan eno tub
,ssenredliw nisnocsiW eht otni daor levarg eht nwod kert ym nageb I sA
.rood eht dnoyeb ro yawllah eht nwod yllaicepsE
,noititsrepus saw ni deveileb I gniht tsal eht ,lla retfA
.detcartsid oot teg ot ton flesym gnilliw
.htolcniol sih htaeneb yal taht eglub a
.em sdrawot deppets nam lakcaj ehT
”…t’ndluoc ti ,oN…taht diD-D“
,hself ffo-raf eht ni ,dlaregztiF gnikcuf nilknarF
!tihs ,tihs ,tihs ,tihS“
lufituaeb…woh fo tcaf eht sa hcum sa ton tub ,em desirprus tahT
.era uoy kniht I tahw eb t’nac uoy…uoy ,oN-
,ekil eht ro ytinaitsirhC fo tces wen a erew yeht demussa saw tI
,hguone ecin demees ,’snitraM miJ reciffO eciloP‘
,seiceps eht gnisufnoc rof flesym gnikcik yllatnem ,dezilaer I ,god a ton ,oN
,rehto eht ni hknA egral a dna
,ecnarF nrehtron fo seniltnorf eht no egalliv deyortsed a gnitisiv tinu ym dellacer I
,sicoV sumoD yb
.sresuort denetsafer sti fo edisni rebmem denedrah ym gninruter
.tisoped 05$ a em dereffo yeht litnu
,rac eht dekcolnu yldrawkwa eH
.ebircsed enola tel dnatsrednu t’ndluoc I slobmys egnarts ni deniadro eno ,yawllah worran a nwod reep ot dnah thgir ym desiar I elihw tuhs rood eht desolc yldnilb dnah tfel yM
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT
.sussim eht yb edam srennid dna sehcnul
.egdub ot desufer ydob yM
.ybraen sesion tcnitsid yna rof denetsil I sa sllaw eht ot eutats eht morf delevart seye ym ,ylsseldniM  .lakcaj a s’tI
.elpoep gniraef-doG dnasuoht-eerht fo nwot a yb deviecrep eb dluoc ti woh tub ,eman eht ni ton
.esac wen ym em ot denialpxe eh sa mih ediseb gnitegdif tnatsissa sih dna ffirehS eht
.elohssa gnilliw s’nam a fo ecneirepxe laer eht pmurt dluoc seiromem lufnis dna evol-fles fo thgin eritne na neve toN
.meht enimaxe ot drawrof deppets ylsuoituac I  .daert devrac hcae no decalp smeti eht dna ratla ediw a fo spets eht ,gniliec eht ,llaw eht no shpylgoreih rehto ehT
,taht ekil gnihtemos od ot naht retteb wenk I dna ymmoT ,detnarG
.llih eht no dnuopmoc eht ot ti edam I ecno od ot tahw no gnisucof emit ym dneps ot derreferp I tub
.deneppah tahw fo noitcellocer a tuohtiw tuo kcab gniklaw dna setag eht edisni gniog si rebmemer nac eh syas mloclaM taht llA
?sesuoh fo swor eht fo egde eht yb epocs eht ni deraeppa tsrif esle ohw
.llib rallod naciremA eht ni eveileb did I tub
.eciffo eekuawliM ym morf edivorp ot secivres rehto ynam desitrevda ’.cnI ,snoitagitsevnI edapS .J‘ hguoht neve ,’retnuh eimmoc‘ a em dellac emoS  ”.esitrepxe…ruoy
.hcruhc rieht rof evas sbmob sixA yb trapa nrot
”…yob dlo ,sussim eht tfel uoy rednow oN“
.neeb dah daeh s’eutats eht noitisop tahw wenk I tcaf eht ta ymmalc gnileef ylneddus niks dna ediw seye
.htimS niatnuoM eht
,thgieh sih ot eud ti gnihcuot ylraen
:esnecni htiw mirb eht ot dellif neeb dah moor enirhs s’elpmet eritne eht rehtehw gninoitseuq em dah was I gniht txen eht ,yltpurbA
.lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF ehT
.mih dniheb elbisiv liat devruc a neve dna srae dekreP
,citsaisuhtne s’nam etihw eht otni deraeppasid ti sa pit suoblub ,krad eht ta denedder dna devruc ylthgils ,ynihs dna kcilS
.rewolloF a emoceb ot efiw sih decrovid ytuped eht retfa stnemyap teg ylraluger yehT
eht fo eno detnaw I sselnu ecnesse eht fo saw emit flesym dednimer neht
.flesym rof enummoC eht ees dluow I ,flesmih liveD eht ro stsinummoc fo kcap ytrid a eb ti rehtehW
.notsip a ekil decar tsehc ym edisni staebtraeh ehT  ”!!nepO !timmad ,nepO
,ytilaer ot kcab deknilb I
.)krow ta stunhguod ynam oot yawa gnikaens ro ,tahT
.did syawla I ,lleH
.nerdlihc eerht htiw nam ylimaf a ,seituped remrof s’ffirehS eht fo eno neve dna nrevat s’nwot eht ta slacol wef a ,yraterces a
.tluc eritne eht ekowa rood eht ta gnillup dna sesruc ym fi em esirprus t’ndluow ti ,ylknarF
.emoh ta leef em edam syawla taht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ythgirlA“  .tneilc ym sa IW ,notrebmiK ekat ot em rof noitavitom ,yllacisaB
,snezitic gninael-tfel tsniaga tnuh hctiw s’yhtraCcM rotaneS ot sknaht
,sgnireffo ,sehtit ni yleritne derevoc ratla eht dnuof osla tinu ym tub ,did ew hcihw ,meht etarebil ot seillA eht rof gnitiaw snailivic deldduh yal edisnI
,htgnel ym nwod dekohc ylhsirevef eh yaw ehT
.hguoht rood eht edistuo morf emoc t’ndid tI .tnemevoM
.su fo daeha daor gnidniw eht no deniamer seye yM
.ytreporp eht no sevlesmeht detalosi yeht erofeb kcab
dna…reirrab eht edisgnola sffats rieht tes ot nam kcalb eht ot gninrut nilknarF ,reirrab hguorht-ees eht ni koorc a yb deppots neht yehT
,sdik dna efiw a htiw eriter ot ecalp ecin a ekil demeeS
eugaelloc/ecnatniauqca/robhgien rieht fi wonk ot detnaw yletarepsed stneilc ym
eseht piks nac uoy
.nees enola tel draeh eb ot ton luferac
.ereht em dnif ot srewolloF
.em ekil nem ecivres ot woh wenk ymmoT
,em ta nwod deknilb gnikcuf eutats eznorb ehT .deknilb ti
.sdnah gnilbmert ym ees em tel ot elba ylerab dna skcarc eht hguorht gnipeerc ,rood eht edistuo thgilnoom tniaf eht morf emac thgil fo ecruos ylno ehT
.detcepxe I naht erom hcum em desserpmi roiretni s’moor ehT
,resolc deppets eh sa gnirats deunitnoc I ”?t’now uoY-Y…Y“
,yks tilnus eht rednu ssarg eht gnola dexaler
.sesseug elpuoc a uoy evig d’I ,lleW
.stekcop peed sti ni neddih noitagitsevni fo stnemurtsni dna em dnuora depard taoc hcnert nworb
,kool resolc a rof gniyV
,taes regnessap eht fo tuo flesym detfil I sa gnihtyna yas t’ndid neht
.stoggaf detesolc fo semoh eht ro syawyella krad ni ,ycavirp nI
etercnoc fo elgnuj
.sgniht setacilpmoc ylniatrec taht ,lleW“
.8102 ni ”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“
?kcuf eht tahW .dessik
,hguoht netfo eroM
dna tsehc delesihc a gnitneserp
.trevrep lauxes a saw I ,seY
.wolg nedlog a ni gnihtyreve gnitsac ,thgil fo secruos ylno eht sa llaw devrac eht gnola denil seldnaC
.yellav eht sdrawot llih eht nwod neht dna sesuoh eht tsap levart meht dehctaw I dna—
seye sih rednu sgab gninekrad eht
”?edapS .rM ,esac eht ekat esaelp uoy lliW
.enummoC eht fo retnec eht raen dnuorgyalp tfihsekam rieht morf eman sih dellac ohw nerdlihc fo puorg a ot evaw ot sa llew sa
1 traP ,sicoV sumoD yb
,nisnocsiW nrehtron ni ot neeb reven d’I nwot a ot yaw eht lla eekuawliM morf evird txen eht gnikat dna esactius ym gnikcap tneps yad rehtona
?evom tsuj daeh sti did
.taorht ym fo kcab eht ni esor sesion revetahw htiw srobhgien eht trela ot em desuac tsomla
.enummoc eht edisni dnuof I tahw rettam t’ndid tI
.emoh fo hcum oot em dednimer ytinummoc tink-esolc a gnidnuorrus smraf ehT
.nwot kcih emos morf ytuped a naht rehtar dnahmraf a ot erom degnoleb taht riah yvaw kcalb ro
,hsalf esnetni na otni demrofsnart ewa denethgirF
,delruc liat sih nehw
?ni kcab em kcol rewolloF a diD
.nwot ot kcab elcric rac eht ees ot kcab kool t’ndid I ,yaw rehtiE
elgnis a htiw em fo tfel taes s’revird eht ni ytuped eht desserdda I
.enummoC eht nioj ot dniheb gnihtyreve tfel yllautca meht fo lareves nehw saw
.elzzum cillatem sti ssorca delims neht
eutats eht fo trap gnikirts tsom ehT
ekil…gaf a s’ytuped sih taht lliH llet nac I ekil toN
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.srewolloF eht sdrawot ecneloiv ni detluser semitemos taht
.yad txen eht erifdliw ekil daerps cinap dehsuh dna sromuR
.dne rehto eht no moor eht morf emac yltniaf taht thgileldnac gniremmihs ni dehtab ,llaw hcae derevoc yeht ,esac eht revetahW
.worbeye desumeb a htiw deohce eh ”?…tuB“
.nisnocsiW fo tolp rieht morf ton nemow dna nem sa llew sa ,ytreporp etavirp eht ot thguorb eb lairetam noitcurtsnoc was klofsnwot eht sa dessap shtnoM
.skcottub devruc sih fo weiv tcefrep a em gnidivorP
.seye deworran ym ot kcab sraluconib eht decalp neht ,htaerb ym rednu derettum I ”…sdrib nmaddog…kcA“
snoitasucca ro serats gninoitseuq ,lufetah nevig rehtie erew yeht ,seilppus rof ni derutnev noitagergnoc eht fo rebmem a revenehw ,woN
,doof nworg-emoh dlos yeht sa gnola tog neve enummoC eht dna notrebmiK
.roolf gnirobhgien eht otno rettil ot nageb hcihw fo emos ,srettel dna shpargotohp ,sehtit ,sgnireffo fo ytnelp dah ylniatrec elpmet eht ni ratla ehT
,elbissop sa ytsejam hcum sa htiw ecnef deknil-niahc eht revo debmilc I ,thgis ni t’nerew sdraug fo tfihs txen eht sa noos sA
.hguorht tnew elas eht os
.elkraps ot kcen sih dnuora ecalkcen hknA eht neve dna stelecarb tsirw
”.teem ot gnisuma tsom eht syawla era cigol fo slatroM“  —seippih esehT
.drawrof gnirats neeb dah daeh depahs-lakcaj s’eutats eht taht nrows evah dluoc I
.sraluconib eht morf seye ym ekat ot gnirad tuohtiw flesym eldnof ot nwod dehcaer ylwols I ,gnikniht tuohtiW
fo mrof emos tlef eh ekil
.yawllah ralugnis eht fo dne eht ta gnidnats
,hguoht raef dna noisufnoc otni kcab demrofsnart tlef I lasuora ynA
.emosenol ym no lla eb d’I
.stnap nottoc yerg sih edisgnola rehtegot cinut sih dleh tleb elpmis a tniop eht ot
,eutats eznorb eht delbmeser eH
a tsdima metsysoce cibohportsualc a
,sdoow eht ni repeed nwod noitanitsed ym rof raef sih eb ti rehtehW
”…gnol oot rof su gnirehtob neeb evah seimmoc kintaeb esohT“ .em morf noitasrevnoc a gnitaitini deirt eh ”,nwo ruoy no lla ereht ni og ot uoy fo evarb ythgim s’tI“  .tnurg
.trAtnaiveD ro noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif osla nac uoY
ssel…rieht fo etips nI
.em denraw dah ffirehs dna royam eht tahw morf ,serca 000,02 revo dennaps ytreporp eritne ’srewolloF ehT  ***
.serutcurts owt dnuora swor ralucric ni pu denil yltaen snibac gol nezod flah a dna owt fo thgis eht ssim dluoc ydoboN
,ksed sih ta yad taht reilrae em dlot lliH royaM
,trapretnuoc cinatit erom sti ekilnU
.flesti efil fo htriber eht neve dna efil ezilobmys ot meht htiw dnuora ti deirrac sdog suoirav s’noitazilivic eht fo ynam
.daeh s’god a gnivah erugif eht devlovni
.deb ni noitca yna nettog t’ndah I
.noitagergnoc wollef sih rof enummoc llams a dliub dluoc eh os dnal eht derised ohw trevnoc-denrut-tsigoloeahcra deriter
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,rehtomdnarg dewodiw a
,on yas ot deraperp saw I
,drow ’stnediser notrebmiK eht ot eurT
.tca lauxesomoh oobat rieht desuap yeht nehw dne na ot emac yllautneve sgniht doog ,yletanutrofnU
.shgiht denniks-krad dna tsehc s’revol sih pu gnileef elihw rebmem ecin taht no htrof dna kcab debbob knarF
—eb ot deneppah mohw fo enO
.esac nmad eht ekat ot tsrif ta tnatculer neeb d’I yhw saw hcihw ,wonk reve dluoc ydobon taht laitnesse ti edam krow fo enil yM
.eekuawliM nwotnwod ssim em edam taht sretspmud egabrag gnittor fo llems dna
.esitrepxe…ruoy fo deen suoires ni t’nerew ew fi ereh pu yaw eht lla uoy dellac evah t’ndluow ew ,edapS .rM ,hguoht dlot eb hturT“
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer
.spil lainigriv-naht-ssel
”…emutsoc neewollaH gnikcuf a eb ot laer oot kool…uoY“
.em brutsid t’ndid ,levarg nevenu otni nrut resiurc ecilop eht htaeneb tlahpsa eht gnileef
.tuo dekcalb I dna
.edisni llits saw dlaregztiF nilknarF fi wonk ot dedeen I
,sbrubus eht fo snoitacoffus eht epacse ot gnitnaw sretnuh wef a dna smraf eht morf emac yenom rieht fo tsoM
.rehto on ekil em deziremsem namsdraug kcalb eht gnicivres yllaro nilknarF fo thgis eht ,esle gnihtemos no sucof ot deirt I sa hcum sA
.eciov sih ot netsil saw od ot dedeen I gniht tsal ehT
gniht…siht htgnerts elbisiv revetahw ot nosirapmoc ni delap ohw ,em htiw tcatnoc eye niatniam ot redro ni drawnwod detlit llits daeh siH
.sthguoht ym morf em deltrats worc A
,tlik a ekil tsiaw sih revo depard taht cinut kcalb kciht a ni noitagergnoc eht fo tser eht morf trapa desserD .dnah ni ffats nedoow a htiw sgnillewd eht fo eno morf gnitixe
ylevil…woh saw hguoht em dexelprep tahW
;etats eht ni esle gnihtyreve ot derapmoc laiceps gnihton saw ni devirra I nwot llams ehT
.segalliv neewteb derahs loohcs eht ni tuo gnidnats owt ro resaerg lanoisacco na
.ecnavda ni diap tog llits I ,yaw rehtiE
”—an ym wonk uoy od woH-
,gniraelc egral a fo ecnedive eht ekuber dluoc ydobon ,ecnef knil-niahc llat a dnoyeB
,noitartsurf )lauxes yltsom( ni dehgis I
.noitalever a hcus sdneherpmoc edapS nhoJ woh
,)sagot nem dna stnap erow nemow emos(
.latem fo edam t’nsaw eh wenk I tpecxe
,taorht ym fo kcab eht pu delevel naom suolaej A
.gat gniyalp nerdlihc gnihgual ,gnirepmacs fo puorg a revo gnihctaw tslihw fael gninnur a detaicerppa ro
,dennalp sa thgin fo daed eht ni em detisiv ymmoT
.ecaf s’lakcaj eht ot denruter noisiv ym dna
”.stsinummoc emoceb ot su gnihsawniarb ro nataS gnippihsrow rehtie eb attog yeht ,ay llet I
.gnihtyna ro erutaN rehtoM tsniaga lanosrep gnihtoN
.tixe eht rof tnirps ot htgnerts eht dnuof yllanif teef ym litnu owt yb dewollof
;ewoD .E nodgnaL eb dluow nam tahT
.retsum dluoc I zzij eht lla dna srallod ytxis fo em deniard reltsuh detnelat taht
”…edapS nhoJ .rM ,yrautcnas siht fo erutan eht tuoba uoy ot kaeps ot hsiw od I“
hguorht gnittuc koorb gnilbbab a htiw ,hguone ytterp demees ni detautis saw ti yellav llams ehT
.pool ralucric eht yb ti gnidloh
”lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF“
.em ni esir ot detrats raef revetahw nwod gniplug ,flesym dlot I ,nwod mlaC
.daeherof ym ot regnif dewalc a detfil eh sa gnilbmur ylwol ,ekops eh
”…tuB !eb t’nac uoY-Y
.tuhs desolc sdnilb eht htiw eciffo niam sih ni ,oga sruoh em dlot royam gnidlab ,ylrub s’notrebmiK tahw dellacer I
,rehtegot deldood senil tsuj srehto ,shpylgoreih erew emoS
.emit emos rof edahs eht ni edam eb d’I neht ,llew tnew sgniht fI
.elpmet enots eht ta sdraug oN
.yhw wonk su fo enon dna ,kcab og ot gnisufer era nem yM“
,ytilaer ot kcab daeh ym gnikahS
,ytreporp eht fo edis rehto eht raen yroirp depahs-ssorc a gnieb meht fo eno ekatsim ylniatrec dluoc ydoboN
.strikstuo eht no enummoC eht ot tnew yehT“
erew srewolloF eht ekil
.sgniht gninigami er’uoY
.mraf eht ot kcab og ot detnaw dna hguone ytic eht detah uoy fi
daer egdab esohw ,yug ehT
,gnillewd hcae neewteb-ni thgilnoom fo swodahs eht ni etsah edam I os ,emac sdraug oN
.delbmurg ffirehs eht ”!gniht nmaddog a toN“
”.uoy truh ton lliw I“
.esac wen ym saw nwot kcih taht ot levart ot dediced I nosaer ylno ehT ?eM
levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
delaever dnal talf fo erca na flah erehw
”,uoy mrah ot hsiw ton od I yas I nehw hguoht ti naem I“  .dessessop
.neht kcab detpmet tlef llits I tub
.esle gnihtemos draeh yllanif I nehw srae ym ni gnignir eht dnoyeb draeh eb dluoc dniw thgin eht neve toN .ecneliS
N…I“ .gninepo no pu nevig gnol d’I taht rood nedoow eht tsniaga desserp kcab
.su neewteb ecnatsid eht morf evisserpmi sa ezingocer dluoc I neve ssenelam kcalb a laever ot tlik eht pu gnillup dnah sih
.taoc hcnert eht rednu retsloh ym debbarg tsomla I sa nezorf dnah eno ,pu desnet yletaidemmi selcsum yM
,enim htiw seye gnikcol elihw sgodtoh fo tseitsat eht ekil ti no gnipruls dna gnipsag
.hcterts eht fo trap rehto yna ekil eb ot ti desseug ev’dluow ylekil I ,stimil nwot eht gniraen erew ew gnitacidni rekram elim eht rof t’nerew ti fI
”!?em gniddik gnikcuF“
,riah kcalb tuc-esolc sih ni gniyerg eht eciton ot seye rieht tniuqs ot deen t’ndid eno ,seitriht etal sih ni nam ylimaf a sA
tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tops gnidih ym morf taerter ot derad I erofeb llafthgin ot denrut thgiliwT
,ralloc nedlog eht desuac hcihw ,etihw esnetni na dewolg seye sih elihw
.yreneerg eht ni meht dnif regnol on dluoc I sa gniffocs
ydob denot-llew ,seye dlareme eht sa hcus serutaef emosdnah sih no toN
,ereht melborp eht ees dluoc uoY
,kcen rieht dnuora ro gnihtolc rieht no lobmys egnarts a erow netfo lakcaJ eht fo srewolloF eht denoitnem ffirehs dna royam ehT
,nehw detapissid erutaN rehtoM sdrawot noitartsurf ym ,yllufknahT  ”.ognib
.tnarraw a teg ot uasuaW morf nem erom ni llac dna tsrow eht emussa dluow yeht neht ,sruoh thgie-ytrof nihtiw nruter t’ndid I fI
.roirp sruoh was I hpargotohp eht ni did eh naht tnereffid tsomla dekool nam eht
,ssorc eht no gnignah tsirhC suseJ ,roivaS dna droL ruo htiw denroda ,wodniw ssalg-deniats tcatni yltneced a fo daetsni ,tpecxE
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
,edistuo sdniw nmutua eht sediseb raeh dluoc I lla ,revewoH
,tiaW…eutats eht ot kcab delevart seye ym erofeb em gnitcartsid ,noisseccus neddus ni derekcilf seldnac ehT
—sih htaenrednu ekil dekool snitraM reciffO tahw enigami ,rO
eritta remrof naht
.rehto hcae ot drow rehtona yas t’ndid eW
.elpmet ekil-dimaryp enots a rehto eht dna
,srewolloF eht fo emos ot elims eniuneg a elims mih dessentiw I .saw eh
,retal sruoh dehsinif erew ew emit eht yB
.duht tfos a htiw edis rehto eht no gnidnal