".ereh tuo uoy pleh
,eciffo eht fo thgis yrros eht ta desufnoc deknilb ehS
?no gniog ytrap azzip a s'ereht ,yeH"
.thguoht fo niart sih fo tuo flow eht deppans hceercs A
stsurc azzip dedracsid gnillips ,rettalc a htiw roolf eht ot llaf ti gnittel dna reniatnoc doof eht no pirg sih gnisaeler ,depsag miJ
.devirra I erofeb sehcnul nelots fo ,neve sraey
.enoyna rof erew sekacpuc revo-tfel eht demussa tsuj ylbaborp raeb ehT .deyalps srae
.yb welf owt rehtona sa elcibuc sih otni dellor miJ
.tohs doog a teg ot revoc dniheb dehcnertne oot saw raeb eht tub trad rehtona derif miJ ".eneG
.rotaregirfer leets sselniats eht nepo gniworht
.nevele ,net ,enin :niaga dna
.hturt eht tnaw I"
.taes ytpme na ylno dnuof eh nehw llef srae siH
",devres eb tsum tub leurc si ecitsuJ"
.egdirf eht ni efas sehcnul rieht peek nac seeyolpmE"
.yadot egdirf eht ni gnihtyreve netae ydaerla ev'uoY"
dnuos yna ta dehctiwt rae s'flow ehT
,reniatnoc eht fo edis eht deye eH
,sreniatnoc ytpme esoht lla htiw ereh gnittis uoy sees dna hcnul rof ereh ni semoc enoyreve ecnO
,smlap laicifitra dna seert sucif klis fo elgnuj llams eht tsap ,aera nepo eht ssorca deppils miJ
.snaeb dna krop elpmiS
,eneG yb dekcipdnah hcae
"?dloraH ,elbuort esuac dna eciffo ym otni emoc nac uoy kniht uoy ,haeY"
,yas ot si tahT--dluow I
!ecreif dna gninnuc
.elcibuc-tuoedih s'dloraH otni deraeppasid dna ria eht hguorht nups yellov ehT
.enot gnikcom a ot eciov reh derewol dna
a ekam ot ekil uoy dluow woh
moor eht revo tpews ecneliS
,mih fo tnorf ni gnidnats raeb eht gnirutcip
.esor demmets elgnis a evah I tub ,eciffo ym ni s'ti sa
.elzzum delffum a hguorht dias eh
ll'ynnaD ,tnempiuqe emos deen uoy ro gnikrow t'nsi retupmoc ruoy fI"
.eson sih hguorht deppils tnarodoed 'srekrow-oc raluger sih dna repap ,eeffoc ,ria delcycer
.yadretsey uoy detivni evah dluohs I"
,reniatnoc evaworcim eht otni lisnetu sih gniggiD
raguoc dega elddim ehT
,edis eht ot srelpats eht dessot eH ".ssenevigrof
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
er'yehT .flesym meht edam I
,dellif ti naht retsaf deitpme nehctik ehT
,doof gnilaets neeb s'ohw eno eht evomer I fi
.dehcterts dna doots miJ ,ksed sih morf yawa riahc sih gnilloR
,dloraH woN" .raeb eht ot pu deppets regdab ehT
.seeyolpme ym lla ot ledom a ma I sa tsuj ,lla ot ssentaerg fo nocaeb a ,eb ot hsiw srewolf rehto lla taht rewolf ehT
.naeco//:sptth :egap yrruFoS rieht no krow rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
.siht ot emoc s'ti nehT"
.em ot sneppah siht netfo woh desirprus eb d'uoY" .deggurhs dloraH
,xorgiT naecO yb
,emihc lanif dna htflewt eht nO
,fehc temruog gnuoy a gnitad ro
.eugnot sih hcuot ot reve azzip tseb eht taeb t'ndluoc srevotfel s'ardnaS nevE
,doof sih dehsinif dloraH
,pu ti dekcip dna dekrep llits srae s'enipul ehT
.dedeen ygolopa oN .ardnaS ,esruoc fO"
.ssenevigrof rof ksa si od nac I llA
.reisae sboj rieht ekam ot derih neeb s'ohw reganam ssecorp yldneirf wen eht ta yrgna ton er'yehT
.delbmert nref ekaf ehT
?thgir ,ronnoC'O dloraH"
"!s'aneleY era esoht--s'tahT"
".daerb hguodruos no
.etteuqite eciffo reporpmi tuoba klat rehtona otni kcab mih gard dluoc dratsum tuoba gnilbmurg s'ardnaS erofeb tfel flow ehT
.tuo elkcirt sbmurc esool wef a dehctaw ehs
,nwod edispu ti gninruT
"!ssenisub tnalp ekaf eht ni owt rebmun ot eerht rebmun morf og nac ew wonk I ,ssenisub ruo tcudnoc ew woh gninilmaerts yB
.daeh sih koohs eH .oN
"?gniod owt uoy era tahW" .miJ detnurg
,yllufgnorw mih esucca eciffo eht ta enoyreve did ylno toN
kcolc ksed s'miJ
gnikcams spil fo dnuos ehT
,yawa daeh sih denrut enipul revlis ehT ".esiannoyam
"!nehctik eht ,ecalp etiruovaf ym s'ereH"
?hcnul rof gnirb eh thgim sthgiled suoiciled tahW
,retnuoc elbram a doots llaw eno gnolA
.retsum dluoc eh lla saw tsehc sih morf elbmur wol a tub ylper ot deirt eH
netfo enim ees ton yam uoY
.meht deteerg etoyoc ynwarcs eht ",ereht iH"
meti lufruoloc tsom ehT
.ffo tfel flow eht erehw pu dekcip dloraH ".esicrexe
.gnihton seod em gnitaefeD
.raeb gnirob ,cisab rehtonA
.tca eht ni mih hctac nac uoy ,won thgir kool uoy fI
,meht tsap dehsup dna htoob eht fo tuo dils enipul ehT
,moor eht dnuora decnalg dna eit sih denesool miJ ".enoyna
.reyalp aidem sih otni nretseW ittehgaps cissalc a dils eh sa dedoorb eH
tnecs eht pu dekcip eson sih sa
.dedeen thgin siht tahw saw noitcelloc DVD sih hguorht kcip kciuq a dna ,stnaptaews
.teerts eht ssorca iled eht si taht
- 6 RAOR ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw yrots sihT
,dik ,yeH" ,deksa miJ ,devirra yob azzip eht nehW
,tuo dellac yllufreehc nageM ,denepo noitpecer ot rood eht nehW
.teerts eht ssorca iled eht fo etsatretfa gnidne-reven eht yawa hsurb dna
.yob yreviled eht rof gnitiaw ,hcuoc sih otno deppolf dna
.wols gniggaw liat sih
".esicrexe gnidliub-maet a dne ot yaw taerg a ekil sdnuoS
.dloraH dehgis ",sehcnul reh gnitae ssim ot gniog m'I"
.teerts eht ssorca iled eht ta gnitae tnaem siht ,yldaS
ylizal deyaws liat siH
.hcnul rof tuo dloraH ekat ot mih gniggan ardnaS derebmemer eh ,ksed sih morf pu doots dna
.ereh uoy gnisucca ton m'I"
.dewob daeh sih htiw meht erofeb gnileenk
.ereh em dnif yllausu nac uoy ,snrecnoc ro snoitseuq yna evah uoy fI"
.ezad krow sih fo tuo mih ekorb
.edis eht no aranobrac ozirohc ycips a htiw nasemrap nekcihc ylevol a saw taht erofeb keew ehT
eciffo eht fo renroc eht ot emac yeht yllautnevE
,dnuora dekool dna ni deklaw ynnaD
,mih retfa desahc bom ehT
.sevlow owt fo hpargotohp demarf elgnis a dna ,kcolc latigid
.ruot eht gnidne moor ylppus eht dna
.eceip tsrif eht otni hteet sih knis dluoc eh erofeb avilas htiw deppird elzzum s'miJ
.ot desu ehs ekil ti ekam t'nac I dab ooT
",staert ytsat hcus sekam amdnarG"
tesolc ylppus eciffo eht hguorht egammur kciuq A
,snoino ,sreppep htiw noitanibmoc ni lla
dekcilf rae s'dloraH "!tnellecxe ,hA"
.moor eht fo tuo dna
.ffo ti dewohs eh sa deggaw liat s'miJ ".ksed ym s'ereH"
pu depmuj neht eH
,citsalp era stnalp ruO
,srekrow-oc yrgna neewteb deppiz daeh s'miJ ".suolucidir
.sraeb fo reyortsed
.laem gnizilatnat taht koot ohw wonk t'nod I taht yas ot yrros m'I ,lleW"
/moc.yrrufos.naeco//:sptth
.syawyna nref a tsuj saw ehs ,llew ,hO"
.retae ysion eht ta gniralg
.deretne tsuj ohw flow eht ta pu gnikool ,ecnetnes-dim deppots nexiv ehT "-
.ksed ydit eht fo tsom deipucco
.smaes eht ta deniarts snottub eht
.elcibuc eht morf tuo dekaeuqs eciov A "!tuo hctaW"
.moor eht otni renroc eht dnuora daeh sih dekaep ynnaD ".ecalper
,shtnom eht rof pu ekam t'nseod noissefnoc ym tuB"
llaw eht revo cra trad maof wolley a ees ot pu decnalg eH
,sretnirp ,smoorhtab ,smoor gniteem :seitinema eciffo rehto suoirav eht ffo dewohs miJ
oyam eltopihc htiw hciwdnas nekcihc enolovorp dna reppep der detsaor A"
.erehwyreve strad maof derettacs
ymafni ot esir ocixeM morf oreh-itna gnuoy eht gnihctaw
"!llew sa uoy truh ylno lliw hturt ehT"
renroc eht dnuora meht detcerid flow ehT ".ruot
.swap s'raeb eht ni snopaew ekaf eht ta ecnalg dluoc eh os elzzum sih nwod sedahs sih dehsup eH
# .yad elbirroh siht rof ekac eht no dratsum eht tsuj saw teerts eht ssorca iled eht ta tae ot decrof gnieB
dehctiwt eye s'miJ ".tsaef
.miJ ot resolc reniatnoc eht degdun eh
deredduhs flow ehT
.nwod dna pu enisru eht dekool seye yls siH ".egdirf
.talps a htiw teprac sih tih tips fo daw ehT
.krow ot kcab ynnaD gnioohs ,ni tuc miJ ".yug
...s'tI" .htrof dna kcab gnigniws liat dna dessorc smra
".erad t'ndluow uoy--uoY"
.eciffo eht deretne eh
.redluohs s'raeb eht revo gnikool
.suolucidir si siht tub ,elihw a rof siht htiw pu gnittup neeb ev'ew ,wonk uoY"
reh deteerg miJ ",ardnaS ,yad dooG"
.enod lleW .miJ ,obmiJ ,ymmiJ ,miJ ,miJ .miJ ,hO"
.neht dnuora uoy wohs em teL"
.ksed reh no srepap fo kcats eht detlusnoc ehs sa ffo deliart ardnaS "...a
dworc eht morf drawrof deppets regdab desserd-llew A
.ybbol eht laever ot srood ssalg detsorf eht fo eno nepo dehsup miJ
.no evom...tsuj s'teL
.daeh ruoy evah ll'yeht
.netae ydaerla ev'I .sknaht on tub ,sknaht hO"
.sdnah daed ,dloc ym morf ti yrp uoy nehw hcnul ym ekat nac uoY"
.ados sih fo spis neewteb flesmih ot derettum miJ ".raeb
?ytrap azzip a tuoba gnihtemos draeh I"
.ralloc sih rednu walc a deppils miJ ".neht
".dloraH rof em tnes ardnaS"
...a saw tI" YADNOM
,taorht s'miJ ni derrits elbmurg wol A ".teerts
.wodniw eciffo eht tuo erats ot denrut dna doots ardnaS ".tnialpmoc
.flesmih ecudortni ot revo deppets miJ
.stcudorp ruo ni edirp ekat ew F-elpirt ta ereh tub ,uoy demrofni enoyna fi erus ton m'I
,nwo ym dekcap dna hcnul ot tuo mih gnikat tuoba togrof I tsael tA
,ereh ni ztlaw tsuj nac uoy kniht uoy ,won dnA"
.eeffoc tunlezah fo puc hserf a htiw ksed sih ot denruter eh
.ksed etanimal reh no nref ekaf dettop eht ediseb meht decalp dna
,slidoffad wolley citsalp fo top a tas retnuoc ksed tnorf eht potA
.dnim sih otni tperc thguoht a ,renroc eht gninruT
.hsuh a htiw dehctaw eciffo eht fo tser ehT .xiS .eviF .ruoF
.erih nopu meht rof ,renwo ynapmoc eht
.dnuora dekool dna
.eid ot deraperp er'uoy nehT"
,dnelb eseehc elbram dna
.ereh si airezziP s'yppiZ ?miJ"
seceip wef a koot ylno ti taht sgnippot dna taem hcum os htiw dekcap eceip hcaE
,emit hcnul tuoba s'tI"
?og lla ti did erehW .on ,on ,oN
.daeh sih ni hcnul morf enecs eht gniyalper
.ylyhs delims dloraH ".hcum yrev uoy knahT"
?yhw wonk ot tnaw uoy ,eniF" .taes
"?snoitpo nagev ynA
,redluohs dna daeh sih neewteb dekcut enohplleC
.pu siht peek t'nac uoY
,spirts eht gnikaT
!suolucidir si sihT"
rezzub 05:11 lausu sti htiw kcolc mrala sih ylnO
.stekcop sih fo tuo gnikeep sresnepsid epat gnikcap fo tes a dna
htoob eht tsniaga gnipmuht liat sih
.dlrow larolf eht fo noitcefrep eht si ti slatep htiw dnomaid A
"?poots-s-S" ,tuo derettups eh ,deyalps s'raE
,eciov sih derewol eh sa denettalf srae s'flow ehT ".ardnaS
.mih dniheb rood eht desolc eh sa
.si ti ereh os ,uoy rof tuo dekcip ev'I tahw gnirednow er'uoy erus m'I"
.ngised dael s'ehs ,mih ot txen aneleY tog ev'eW .noitubirtsid fo egrahc ni s'eh ,werdnA si ereht revO"
.mih revo deifirroh gnidnats aneleY ees ot pu dekool eH
.elddim eht ni elbat a dnuora derehtag roolf eht morf seeyolpme eht lla ,edisnI
.tnecca nacixeM ekaf a ot degnahc eciov siH .dereens flow ehT "?miJ"
,lluf htuom sih htiw deklat raeb ehT
.snaeb deirfer dna ecir eht pu derrits eh
"!miJ ,yeH" .thguoht eh
"!namssorG ,skcirt ruoy ot esiw ydaerla m'I"
.eciffo siht ni emit ot emit morf stfeht hcnul neeb syawla ev'erehT
wap a htiw derutseg xof ehT ".ereht
.iled eht ot mih ekat ll'I ,ylniatreC"
,redloh drac ssenisub a
azzip mraw fo secils kciht ehT
- egdirf nerrab eht ni enola tas meti eno ylnO
stroper dna srepap fo skcats dezinagrO
.raeb eht morf ssorca taes eht otni dils eH
.ardnaS dnif ll'uoy tfel eht nO"
,prub suoixonbo ,llams a tuo gnittel retfA
,pu gnarps miJ "!ti s'tahT"
.eniN .thgiE .neveS
ssenisub od ew yaw eht gnizimitpo eb lliw ohw eno eht ot nevig eb dluoc liated tsellams eht dna
"!hgrA" .taoc nworb kciht sih otni elpats retfa elpats gnirif dna
.eciffo s'eneG gnivael
,ybbol eht fo elddim eht ni doots flow ehT
.tsaef nailatI suoiciled a dah tsuj I
.enim eb won lliw
"?azzip lla uoy syub eh esuaceb tsuj lla ti tegrof uoy neht dna ,eciffo eht fo elddim eht ni thgif yalp hsidlihc ,evitpursid ,suolucidir a sah ,shtnom rof sehcnul ruo slaets miJ"
.edis eht no eman ruoy gnitrops reniatnoc elbavaworcim a ekil dekool tahw gniruoved
,egdirf eht morf sregal ytsorf owt
.erolag sevilo dna smoorhsum
.mih dniheb dehsiws liat s'miJ
.dehctiwt eye s'miJ
"!hcnul ym saw taht ,yeH"
,tsud fo llems lausu ehT
.deknilb regdab ehT
.thgir eb thgim uoy ,wonk uoY"
.hsalf a ni yb deppils gninrom s'miJ
"?gniog yad ruoy s'woH"
.flesruoy enod tuo ev'uoY" .semit wef a swap reh deppalc ardnaS ".enod
.noitailater ni derif dna
.teerts eht ssorca morf sehciwdnas lla meht yub ot mih gnicrof retfa nevE
,sneppah taht ecnO
hcnul ot mih ekat ot emoclew er'uoy tub
.sreniatnoc hcnul dedracsid dna ytpme tas mih fo tnorf nI
"!miJ" --skniht eh fI
?skcits daerb revotfel emos ekil uoy dluoW"
reeb rehtona nepo dekcarc miJ
"!ti ekam reven ll'uoY"
sessecorp ruo koolrevo ot eeyolpme wen a derih sah tnemeganam
.nehctik eht fo tuo dellorts raeb ehT ".miJ
.yawllah eht morf meht gnitarapes ksed elgnis a htiw sllaw eht derevoc sdroc dna scinortcele fo sevlehS
raeb eht ot top eht dednah regdab ehT ".rehtegot
.denethgit pirg s'raeb eht
.dehceercs ardnaS "?tahW !tiaW"
.eit deniats ,dekoorc dna
,reniatnoc eht dnuora sdnah sih depparw eh sa
.rehtegot krow dna
.ynoga ni tuo deirc dloraH
allerazzom detlem eht htiw dexim inoreppep dna ,mah ,imalas
,snogardpans lufruoloc sih ot txen nwod gum eht gnitteS
.ecnahc sih saw woN
"?feiht hcnul eht gnieb fo erih wen eht gnisucca
.setaicossa erom tuo gnitniop
.emoh pirt elohw eht deklus miJ # "!emithcnuL !seY"
.swap sih ni srelpats eht gniggans ,sedis sih morf pu smra sih deksihw dna
niaga kcurts kcolc ehT .rehgih dna
.nehctik eht ot yaw sih ekam ot emit saw ti taht mih dlot kcolc sih no mrala 05:11 ehT .hcnul rof thguorb ehs srevotfel eht ta gninialpmoc t'nsaw eh tub
.naelc regnif laudividni hcae dekcus dloraH ".nalp
.reeb yna rof egdirf eht gnihcraes elihw sazzip etiruovaf sih fo rehtona deredro miJ
"?tey enoyna tem uoy evaH" .dennirg miJ ".ereh
.swalc sih rednu morf sbmurc emos tuo gnikcip ,deddon miJ ".dedeen
".gniyap s'ynapmoC
.yug TI ruo ,ynnaD si sihT" .deddon dloraH ".potksed
si yrots s’yadot dna ,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.erom tuo mih maer ot detnaw yeht ecnis yrgna ro
,srevlover ykaeuqs citsalp fo riap a gnihsidnarb
,wonk ot dooG" .delims dloraH ".emityna
"?worromot tuoba woH .dab yM
.elbat eht dehcaorppa eh sa
.teerts eht ssorca iled eht ta gnitae tnaem ti ,llitS
,neercs eht ta deworran s'eye s'miJ
.staert edamdnah ,yragus eht fo yromem eht gninruom
,ti ta kool I yaw ehT"
.reniatnoc elprup ytpme eht pu dekcip ehs sa skeehc s'ssenoil eht nwod llef sraeT "...seikooc
,thgiarts pu gnidnatS
doof sih dewehc-flah raeb eht sa nezorf
,reh dniheb gnihsal liaT
.draobyek s'dloraH no sehctolps deruoloc fo ssem ykcits eht ta degnirc miJ
.napaJ morf emac scinortcele wenk eh esuaceb oobmab esohc eh
,mih dniheb rood s'reganam RH eht desolc eH
.rehto hcae fo pot no meht dekcats dna
.tsrubtuo taht rof ezigolopa I .yrros ,yrroS"
.etalocohc dna secips fo noitanibmoc eht ta gniffins
.elbide gnihtyreve ,lleW
.htaerb sih rednu desruc flow ehT
.tsugsid dna lavorppasid htiw nwod mih gnirats eno hcae
,airezzip eciohc sih ot llac kciuq A .gnineve 'emiT-
,edisa elfir sih gnitteS
yawa dedaf yllanif seton ruos eht
,detas saw ylleb sih erofeb
.gnirevawnu ,llat doots owt ehT ".siht
ria eht decreip kaerts egnaro gniltsihw ehT
.relpats a htiw raeb eht degdun miJ ".hturt
".seikooc reh tae reven d'I .narG-narG evol I"
.sresnepsid epat eht tuo dellup eh
,enisru eht ta meht gnitnioP
.elbat eht no enola tfel sreniatnoc hcnul eht
slaem suoiciled rieht gnikat
,netae dna gnissim og ot seunitnoc hcnul s'enoyreve fI
.revoc rof gnillor dna
.noitsegid rof doog saw aet neerg draeh eneG esuaceb edam yllaiceps ,stnalp aet neerg ekaf fo top a htiw hcae
.dworc eht tsgnoma deohce psag A ".sehcnul
.revo meht gnidaer ,steehs fo tes delpats a tuo dellup dna
krop ozirohc dedderhs detser lla ti fo pot nO
sessalg demmir-kciht reh detsujda raguoc ynwat eht
.avilas tneps sih htiw gnixim dna
.gniunitnoc erofeb wollaws ot desuap eH
raeb eht gnifarts ,rehto eht retfa eno meht dezeeuqs eh
...esuaceb raf og ot evah t'now uoy tuB
.srevotfel rieht tsniaga semirc rof tuo mih gnillac dna egnever rof yrgnuh
:snogardpans klis fo oirt tnarbiv a saw
.namssorG miJ ,reganam selas dezirp ruo naht rehto enon si tidnab hcnul eht taht si eciffo eht dnuora droW"
.eson sih gnilkcit ssenteews yragus fo stnecs
,dnuora dloraH dediug miJ sa senohp ksed gnignir dna
.lla retfa ytrap gnimoclew sih rof thguob erew yehT
.ekatsim yb reniatnoc gnorw eht debbarg evah yam I
.ereh eb ot yppaH" .taes sih morf esor dna dnah s'flow eht koohs raeb ehT "!olleH"
.wap a dereffo dna
.setaicossa suoirav tuo gnitniop detrats miJ
.tsinoitpecer yreehc dna thgirb a rof
"!wol wen a si siht ,miJ ,woW"
:ecaps rof thguof smeti rehto wef A
,yawa gnikrow dna gniwehc ylippah tas dloraH
,nosmirc ,ogidni
.dloraH no ni deworran seye s'miJ
.kaerb rieht rof moor hcnul eht otni gnilif ydaerla erew setaicossa rehto ehT
.raguoc ot kcab neht
.eta eh sa smug sih gnikcams
;reggirt sih dezeeuqs flow ehT
.regnif a desiar ardnaS ".oslA"
,oirt taem eht fo tnecs ehT .delbuod osla
,evom ot rehto hcae derad
,olleh a dna elims lufreehc a nageM gniviG
?ztup a rof em ekat yltsenoh uoy oD" .ksed eht no swoble reh gnitser
.reganam selas ruoy eb ot evresed t'nod I
?tae ot etib a barg annaw uoy
.seye sih revo meht dils dna
,feilebsid ni gnirats eneG ees ot dnuora detsiwt oud ehT
,ksed reh revo denael raguoc ehT
.tnialpmoc hcae etagitsevni ot deriuqer er'eW
.kcab s'miJ no ruf eht nwod delppir redduhs A
.neht dna won hciwdnas a gnirahs snaem taht fi neve ,nac ew reverehw tuo pleh dna ni hctip ot deen lla eW .drah krow seeyolpme ruO
,sreh ediseb eciffo eht ot nar raguoc ehT .ardnaS demaercs
,pmul a ekil tas dloraH
,ylwols deddon dloraH ".yldneirf
.ylteiuq gnittis raeb nworb-tuntsehc ,egral eht ot
elfir sih deppord miJ ".sdnah
.em tog uoY !yako ,yakO"
tnaW" .dnah sih ni gab citsalp eht morf wef a miJ dereffo dna secils tiurf deird no dehcnum etoyoc ehT
.kcans noonretfa na rof esoht evah ot gnipoh saw I ,nmaD
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ria eht hguorht deltsihw strad maoF
.lamron ot kcab deppans eciov s'miJ
,egdirf eciffo eht ni azzip revotfel sih ffo pord ot klaw ksirb a retfA
.metsys ertaeht emoh s'miJ no thgif erif gniralb eht revo dnuos a ekam ot deganam ylerab llebrood ehT
,tnalp ekaf lanosrep a tas sexobliam rieht fo hcae ot txeN
"!siht gniod peek t'nac uoY"
".uoy ron I rehtieN .sniw eno on
.ytisoreneg sih rof lufetarg neeb evah tsael ta dluoc yeht tub
puorg eht tsap depmots ehs
er'yehT" .ria eht ni wap a
ylleb s'miJ YADSEUT
.elzzum yerg sih morf ecuas etihw-hsidder ,ymaerc fo pord llams a yawa gnipiw dna
.syawla sa emas eht gnikool reh ediseb slidoffad klis ,ksed reh yb tas nageM
"!arolF dna snreF ekaF ot emocleW
.ynomerec s'yadretsey morf sekacpuc revotfel eht netae dah raeb ehT
"!ti od t'ndid I !em t'nsaw tI" ,gnilley ,yawllah eht otni tuo gnihsad
.s'ynnaD t'nsaw ereht ni gniht ylno eht sa gnol sA
,egdirf eht ot revo deklaw eh ,gurhs a htiW
".sruoy ot txen era elcibuc dna ksed siH
,elip eht morf eerf ti gniggut dna mrof tnialpmoc wolley eht gnidniF
swap sih ni seikooc gniniamer eht koot eh sa
.lufhtuom a hguorht demialcxe dloraH "!miJ"
,sralom sih dnuorg miJ ".yad
.dab os t'nsi ffo looc ot yad a reh gnivig ,ardnaS 'lo yknarc htiw gniteem s'yadnoM retfa ,llew hO
arolF ekaF dna sdueF
.mih dniheb gniggaw liat
.elohw seikooc eht wollaws ot delggurts dna
".eciffo eht ni emit tsrif ym si siht os enohp eht revo derih saw I .yllanosrep toN"
.sedis citsalp eht otni gniggid swalc
.ees ll'uoY" .redluohs eht no raeb eht dettap flow ehT ".maet
.delims dna mih ees ot denrut ruf fo kluh nworb-tuntsehc A
,hgis dehsilpmocca na htiw riahc sih ni kcab gninaeL
,ynnaD rof tnalp a gnikcip ot emac ti nehw ,suhT
.su fo htob eht rof hguone gib t'nia eciffo sihT"
.etib hcae htiw hctiwt ot liat s'miJ desuac mih fo tnorf ni retae yppols gninekcis ehT
.ylleb dnuor sih dettap dna kcab denael dloraH .dehgis dna
.mih morf ssorca tis ot flow eht rof wap ytaem a htiw derutseg eh
.thgif eht hsinif ot meht gnigru srekrow-oc rieht
.saw enoyreve erehw gnirednow
,mih dniheb gnidnats ylgums ardnaS
.emoclew arolF dna snreF ekaF mraw a nevig s'eh erus ekam ll'I"
.sih ediseb elcibuc ytpme eht ot denoitom dna
,tnemom a rof desuap dloraH "?yeht erA"
,eciffo eht ot ecnatsid gniklaw nihtiw tnaruatser eno ylno saw ereht yhw gninoitseuq dna hsawhtuom fo egasod suorogir a retfA
.delims eh dna ,dekrep srae siH "!hO"
".su fo htob eht rof hguone gib t'nia nwot sihT" ,delrans eH
-ehS" .elit eht ssorca
yenom fo egnahcxe kciuq A
noisicerp hcus ot detacided tnalp a ylnO" .eert iasnob
.taht fo egatnavda ekat ll'I erus m'I
.thgiarts seitiroirp ruoy evah uoy dalg m'I .owt uoy krow taerG"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
"?ereh tuo yaw eht lla reviled meht evah ot artxe diap uoy dias yehT
.seotatop depollacs nocab dna eseehc htiw teksirb feeb eniw der a saw keew tsaL
”arolF ekaF dna sdueF ,dooF“
,gniylper ,drawrof deppets werdnA
.lla uoy degnorw ev'I .thgir s'eH"
,etagitsevni ot revo emac yeht ,htoob eht ta enecs eht gnicitoN
,deddon miJ .htaed gningief
.hcnul ruoy yojnE
.lluf krof rehtona koot dloraH ".ot
.sepicer dlo s'amdnarg fo eno tsuJ ?siht hO"
,detaeper flow ehT ".su
setunim fo rettam a ni elbirroh ot taerg morf enog dah yad siH
".ti koot ohw wonk ot ekil dluow lla ew
".emoc dluow uoy wenk I"
.nugeb ydaerla s'tI"
".hcnul ylrae rehtona no dediced I taht yrgnuh os tog I sseug I
.flesmih ot gnilbmurg ,ffo degdurt miJ
.won tuoba taerg sdnuos hcnuL .delims eh
.krow ot thgiarts tnew miJ
,ti evorp ot elba neeb t'nevah I esuaceb tsuJ"
.deltsirb ruf s'flow ehT
.yad eht hguorht em teg pleh dluow hcnul emos gnipoh saw I"
.enoyna eb dluoc tI"
ecaf reh pu dehcnurcs ardnaS ".uoy
.ffirehS ,taht rof etal oot s'ti kniht I"
aloc fo snac fo elpuoc a debbarg enipul detaefed eht ,enon gnidniF
.eciffo eht otni pets dluoc dloraH os nepo rood ybbol eht dleh miJ ".neht
saw sihT".ynnaD ,tsol teG"
"?ereh no gniog s'tahW"
gnillips aloc sih
,liaw a tuo tel aneleY ".seikooc
.edisni mih detivni ardnaS erofeb dewollof taht hgis detatiga eht ta dekrep srae s'miJ
.seikooc ym erew esoht fi wonk t'nod I
.reniatnoc sih tuo dellup dna ,ti denepo
.tuo deppets ardnaS dna
,denruter eciov gnihceercs s'ardnaS
.rehtegot swap reh depsalc ehs sa sredluohs reh gniggas ,dehgis ehS
,tleb sih ot dekooh ,srelpats fo riap a lanesra sih ot dedda flow eht dna
,eeyolpme hcae rof ,oS .ecudorp ew stnalp suolubaf eht ot detcennoc leef dluohs lla eW
.egavlas ot egdirf eht ni tfel gnihtemos eb d'ereht ebyaM
teg ot tfel sah ehs lla er'yehT .seikooc s'narG-narG laets ot sa wol os poots t'ndluow I nevE !krow retfa yadsruhT hcae stisiv ehs nehw emoh eht ni narG-narG ot meht reviled nac ehs os thgin yadsendeW yreve meht ekam yehT
moor eht gnillif tnecs enipul eht ,denrut enoyrevE
kcip tcefrep eht
doof fo sllems yna fo ecnesba eht ta dennirg enipul ehT
,emit elohw eht ereh neeb s'ohw eno eht trapa raet ot ydaer er'yeht ,oN
.gninrom txen eht pets sih ni ecnuob a dah enipul ehT YADSRUHT
.dekrep srae s'flow ehT ".enim
",ynnaD ,yawa oG" "--fo lluf ,eerf-netulg ,yhtlaeH !taerg
.ycneiciffe ruo evorpmi ot od nac ew tahw ees dna sessecorp ruo revo og ot draob no dloraH thguorb ev'I
;denepeed gnihtaerb s'ardnaS
.RH ot rood eht no deppar eH
.derif srethgifnug htoB
skeehc sih otni staert dekab eht devohs eh ,ediw gninepO
.ruoh noon eht ot resolc gnikcit saw kcolc ehT
.dehctiwt dna srae reh deggut ardnaS
eM' a eb dluow ti dediced miJ
.tnetnocsid htiw delbmur
.nihtiw deniatnoc selif eht hguorht dekcip dna
.elzzum denetrohs reh fo egdirb eht dezeeuqs dna
,nirg gums a evag dloraH ".hcnul
.sekam amdnarg ym seno eht ekil tsuj etsat esehT ?erus uoy erA"
.edirp htiw egdab ynihs sih deyalpsid ffirehs neercs-no ehT
.stellub fo ezalb a ni
deknilb flow ehT ".em
. xorgiT naecO yb
.tsacdop stnoF dna sgnaF eht dna ygolohtna stcA namuhnI eht rof nwonk
.sehcnul s'enoyreve eta I !ti did I
.maet tneiciffe erom a eb nac ew os meht etadpu dna
"!uoy fo lla eveileb
won thgir ereh fo tuo hcram uoY"
,yltnetni dehctaw miJ ".ffirehS
.sedahs rotaiva egral fo riap a dniheb morf reh ta devaw miJ ",nageM iH" "?miJ"
.sreggirt deruoloc thgirb tsniaga dils sregnif yhctiwT
.meht dniheb demoob eciov A
,gnola dloraH gnirehsU
llaw eht morf nwod kcab flesmih derewol ylwols eH
.ykcul saw oobmab draeh d'eh ,sulP
,yadot etal oot s'tI"
doof rof esucxe yrros eht no reffus ot meht gnicrof dna
,teerts eht ni sukcur a gnisuac stidnab eht ot tuo dellac eH
"?elbuort esuac dna nwot ym otni emoc nac uoy kniht uoY"
.hcnul rof emit tsomlA
trihs sserd wolley ni dekcut flah sih htiw dehsalc
.stoohs oobmab retseylop eerht tas ksed s'etoyoc eht potA
.devaw dna pu doots
"?nacixeM ?hsinapS...saw rehtomdnarg ruoy ezilaer t'ndid I"
.ylf sllab epat sih tel dna llaw eht revo dekeep eH
.draobyek sih no gnillaf aslas dna ecir fo stib
.esoht dekab yeht--sbuc reh-
,mih dniheb thguoht eht tup dna
"!laer si ytilauq ruo tub
.rood eht no gnignab
.elims etihw ,thgirb a reh dehsalf flow ehT ".nageM
,ksed eht rednu morf tuo delwarc erugif yerg dna wolley a dna kcab deppets eh sa denediw seye s'raeb ehT
talf llef srae s'miJ "?ton yhw dnA"
.gnitsorf letsap eulb dna knip rieht htiw seikooc gniniamer owt tsal eht ta nwod gnicnalg
.maet eht snioj rebmem wen a nehw evah ot sekil eneG noitidart elttil ,seY"
.kcab gnirats 34:11 srebmun eht ees ot kcolc ksed sih ta decnalg eH
"!yadot sdeed ruoy tuoba hturt eht wonk lliw elpoep ehT"
.tsehc s'raguoc eht ni delbmur elkcuhc A ".tca
,nogard laer a ekil hcum
.ronnoC'O dloraH retsim a ,og ew ereh ,seY"
rood egdirf eht desolc miJ
.etoyoc eht ta deralg miJ
.srehto eht htiw reniatnoc a otni tsurc azzip revo tfel eht gnissot
,spil sih dekcil miJ
.redluohs s'dloraH kcurts dna
.esicrexe gnidliub maet A-
.ruf s'flow eht no selkcah eht gnisiar etib hcae ,ylduol gniwehc
.derewsna miJ ".tiuq ardnaS"
.moorhcnul egral a otni
.wap ykcits a devaw dloraH ".netae
.trad rehtona derif dna ksed sih fo revoc eht morf depael miJ
,stohs ffo gnirif ,deeps gninthgil htiw werd ffirehs eht dna odarepsed eht
,dnah ni kroF .won tsuj mih was I ,tcaf nI
?uoy dluoc woh-
.ksed eht no esacfeirb sih ecalp ot drawrof deppets eh sa
”arolF ekaF dna sdueF ,dooF“
".ksed ruoy si sihT"
depoord nirg yhtoot kramedart s'miJ
esaerg fo tnecs A
.hguoht tressed rof moor emos evas did I"
...seikooc s'narG-narG
tnim htaerb sih gniwollaws
.nalp a ekil sdnuoS"
.deknilb dloraH "?ynomereC"
!pots ,thgirlA" .dedecnoc eh did seceip revlis niht fo egarrab rehtona ffo derif miJ nehw ylnO .decamirg dloraH ".raelc
# .thgin doog a saw thginoT .siht dedeen I
.derab sgnaf dna talf srae
devaw eneG ".reh rof dekcip I tnalp eht s'tahT"
-aF ot emoclew dna gninrom dooG"
dna elcibuc ybraen a otni devid dloraH
,resolc ni denael miJ
.elcibuc s'dloraH tsap deklaw dna
"?tahw ,tiaW" .strad maof
.selas dna gnitekram fo daeh ,namssorG miJ m'I
,rorroh ni dehctaw miJ .dewehc dna
srotaiva detnit kcalb fo riap nwo sih tuo dellup enisru ehT
.miJ no deggard keew eht fo elddim eht fo erusserp ehT YADSENDEW
.llaw elcibuc sih revo dereep eh sa
.raeb mucs ,lerdnuocs ,dednah-ytrid ,doog oN"
.mih revo gnilims ynnaD ees ot pu dekool flow ehT
.eciffo eht fo stnecs eht ni koot dna denway eH
emoh hsad enipul eht dluoc dedne krow ecno ylnO
.worb sih no noisufnoc fo kool a
.tcatnoc eye gnidiova
.ecalper ot ysae dna ,elpmis ,gnirob
.raeb gnivinnoc taht ot sknaht
elzzum s'dloraH pu dils nirg dekciw A ".kcehc em teL
:ottom ruo rebmemer tsuJ" .dnah eerf sih koohs dna
yawa nrow eht tuo gnikam
.yadot hcnul od d'ew dloraH dlot I .flesmih ot derettum miJ ",parC"
"!dratsum ni gninword daerb rieht evah ot ekil t'nod
gnikcalc draobyek htiw demmuh eciffo ehT ".esaelp
,kcab elfir yot eht no noitca eht dils miJ ".eid
.tuo daeh sih dekop regdab eht dna denepo eciffo s'eneG ot rood ehT
.eneG gnitteg m'I
.ybbol eht ni tuo gnitiaw eb dluohs eH
.tsehc sih ta dehctulc dna snug citsalp sih deppord raeb ehT ".em
.miJ ta dereens dloraH
.ruf s'dloraH ni gniruoloc eulb dna wolley fo segdums tuo gnikcip
.kawht gniyfsitas a htiw neercs retupmoc sih ot kcits dna
.ereht revo s'eh ,esruoc fO"
.rehto hcae ta deralg srekrow-oc owt eht ,deunitnoc sezzub eht sA .eerhT .owT .enO
.trad rehtona erif ot pu gnippoP .detuohs miJ
ssol sih tuoba delbmurg miJ
"?gniod uoy era tahw dnA
,dnuora decnalg flow dna raeb eht sa
.eruliaf detcepxenu na saw taht lleW
.deppalc yletilop elpoep wef A
yaw eht fo tuo tnalp aet neerg dettop eht dehsup dloraH ".hguoht
taht saw gninosaer s'eneG .knip dna
noonretfa-dim saw tI
"!tiuq I !ti s'tahT"
tidnab suoiretsym eht wonk t'nod I tahT
setalp maoforytS dna skrof ,snikpan fo elip A
- edis eht no srettel
.taorht sih deraelc dna
.hcnul rof srevotfel gnivael ylisae
.flow eht dna doof eht neewteb decnad seye s'dloraH "...llew
"?meht ekat ot seunitnoc ohw
.em fo lufemahs saw tI .gniksa tuohtiw doof suoicerp ruoy nekat ev'I
revo spets wef a koot flow ehT "...esuaceb
?eciffo eht dnuora mih wohs esaelp uoy dluoC
# .hciwdnas sih otni delbmum miJ
,dooF:yojne esaelP
.ettelap sih evael ton dluow taem iled pmil dna daerb elats fo etsat gnitsugsid eht
.eciffo eht otni tuo pils ot egartuo reh fo yna gnitneverp
,miJ ta derats raeb ehT ".ylimaf
.seilppus eciffo eht gnilttar dna sevael s'nref eht gnikahs
".keew hcae evres yeht saep yhsum dna senurp dewets fo slaem elbirret eht hguorht reh
?yadot elbaliava eb dluow seicaciled tahW
.ocserf oseuq htiw deppot
,rotide dna rohtua gninniw drawa na si naecO .”slerdnuocS“
.deddon dna deplug miJ ".hcnul
su fo emos taht ezilaer t'nseod ro
spil sih dekcil flow ehT
fo riap nwo rieht erif ot ydaer dna demirp
.nehctik eht revo elur sih gnignellahc dloraH
.ksed eht fo gnirevoc etanimal eht otni gud swalc dednetxe reh
elif a werdhtiw ardnaS ".maet
.resolc reniatnoc elprup thgirb a dellup dna
t'nac I" .reehc a ni tuo tsrub srekrow-oc siH
.seilihc dna akirpap fo
.tuo ti derugif reven I naem t'nseod
.llew gnitae eb tsum s'dloraH ekil ylleb a htiw raeb A
.trugoy nialp edam-emoh dna
,pot eht ffo gnippoP
,lattuber a reffo dluoc raguoc eht erofeB ".sraeb
.ria eht hguorht tuc niap fo yrc A
,nehctik eht ot dehsur flow ehT
.shtoob eht fo eno ot revo ezag sih detcerid daerb dna
.esaelp won yawa oG"
,sdaeb dna scirbaf edart-riaf nevow fo edam ,stsirw sih no stelecarb pmeh ehT
dexaler eh erofeb ecaf s'raeb eht dessorc niap fo kaerts A
,maof gniylf egnaro noen eht morf yawa
,eeffoc fo spuc kcab dessot ro retaw htiw delgrag eh gnol woh rettam oN
.smitciv osla sevlesmeht dnif ot ylno
.seson rieht gnihctiwt dna
.yad eht fo tser eht rof miJ htiw kcuts dratsum prahs dna tuarkreuas ymils ehT
,elcibuc sih morf tuo deppets dloraH
".ynomerec eht ta sevlesmeht ecudortni ll'yeht erus m'I tub ,won thgir ysub kool yehT
.ksed eht rednu kcab flesreh deleehw dna
"?gniniatretne boj llud a sekam ti tsael tA"
.eruces dna efas ,sksed rieht ni ti peek ll'yehT
poots d'uoy kniht ot ,sraey eseht lla retfA
.yrdraziw-onhcet fo mrof a sa
.hteet sih neewteb kcuts sreppep dna hcanips fo stib htiw
,drawrof denael dloraH ".daeh
.teef s'dloraH ta taps miJ
.miJ ,hcnul doog a evaH
.ruf sih ot kcuts sllab epat owt eht ffo ekahs ot gniyrt ,gnilialf mra sih
.taes sih morf esor dna delims flow ehT ".emoclew
.esacfeirb nrow a deppirg swap siH
-woH" .elbat eht tuoba derettacs sreniatnoc ytpme eht ta
# ".lla uoy htiw krow ot taert tnasaelp a eb lliw tI"
.ssob dna rednuof ruo ,eneG si thgir eht no dnA"
.gniyarts reven seye
.nirg bmud taht htiw mih gnikcom
.hcnul ruoy gnitae si dloraH eveileb I
.doots srood owt erehw
rehgih noisnet eht gnisir lleb eht fo ekirts hcae
no gnikrow saw eh tnemucod eht devas miJ sA
.noonretfa eht fo tser eht rof mih ta deralg yeht
.egdab s'ffirehs eht htiw regdab trohs eht no ni demooz aremac ehT
xorgiT naecO yB
:swap sih ni saw azzip exuled elbuod elbuod etiruovaf s'miJ dna
stenibac suoirav
.ffo meht gnittuc erofeb tuo leer epat gnikcap fo spirts gnol owt tel eH
.srae s'flow eht dekrep
,nepo ediw kcatta fo wodniw ehT
?neeb uoy evah erehW !miJ"
.llaw elcibuc eht revo stohs owt derif dna
.doof gnirb regnol on ll'yeht
.eerf s'ti tsael tA
demoorg ,citsalp a delaever eneG ".si
.hcnul tsuj s'ti ,ardnaS ,won ,woN"
.smraerif ediseb delgnad stigid yrruf sa
.ffuts hsum trid eerf-netulg edart-riaf nagev yos diputS
kcohs ni ecaf reh dehctulc ssenoil ehT
.tuo edis ykcits ,sllab epat laudividni nwo rieht otni meht dellor eh
s'thgin yadseuT no sessalc gnikooc gnidnetta saw raguoc eht fi erus t'nsaw eH
,roolf eht no despalloc eh litnu gnihguoc otni denrut taht rethgual lacainam otni detpure raeb ehT ".gnihton
"?gnitae uoy era tahW
'sohcahcuM' .oreh noitca eht htiw snortap rab eht lla ta toohs ot dedneterp eh sa reeb fo elttob sih gnihsols ,neercs no rotca gnignilsnug eht detatimi miJ ".nem fo reyortsed ,aesoH ma I"
.gnikcud miJ tnes tohs rehtona fo pans ehT
"?ereh no gniog si tahW"
.ecnartne eht raen ,tfel rieht no elcibuc a ot detniop miJ ".ees
.edis sih ot depparts retoohs-xis ynihs a gnilaever
,thgir hciwdnas ruoy seraperp reven iled taht ebyam lleW"
tih eht ta deliaw raeb ehT
.evlewT .nevelE .neT
.rekrow-oc niurb sih ta llaw elcibuc eht revo gnireep dna gninrut daetsni
.dloraH" "!miJ ih ,hO"
neercs no oud ehT
.pu kcab sedahs sih gnihsup ,deggurhs neht dna
.ecalp otni elttes ot detrats ruf s'miJ dna
,shtoob dna selbat erew moor eht dnuora daerpS
.rebmahc sti ni trad maof eht demirp edisni citsale eht sa kcilc gnidnuoser a gnikam nopaew eht
,trihs etihw sih fo sdnuob eht ta gnihsup ylleb egral sih
ecir niarg elohw nworb no yrruc yekrufot htiw reniatnoc hguorht-ees s'ynnaD
.ylwols denrut dna
.esiannoyam ot cigrella m'I ,wonk I sa raf sA"
.seikooc s'narG-narG...nevE"
"?nref a s'ehs ,tiaW"
.htuom sih otni meht demmarc dna
.eciffo eht fo renroc rehtona ot nehctik eht hguorht deunitnoc owt ehT ".taht
.eciffo sih morf tuo deppets ssob ehT ".syawyna
,taoc sih yawa dellup nialliv ehT
.ecir dna snaeb ,ollag ed ocip
?spihc elppa detardyhed emos
eneG yb dedrager erew tnemtraped TI eht fo slliks ehT
.eciffo sih ot kcab dedaeh dna denrut eneG ".eunitnoC
"?emit eritne siht snug yot fo riap a dnuora gniyrrac neeb evah yllautca...uoY"
.ruovalf eht gnirebmemer
aneleY ot devaw miJ
,aesoH ma I .miJ on si erehT"
.meht tneserper ot tnalp a tuo kcip I
,rood eht ot gnihsad flow yspit ylthgils eht gnidnes
.krow ot kcab teg uoy tel dluohs I"
-hU" .rewsna na rof gnikool ,deremmats miJ ".hu-hu...s'tI"
.raelc dna duoL .yadretsey did uoy tahw ecneidua ruo lleT"
eciffo eht otni deppets miJ
?enog evah sehcnul gnissim eht erehw wonk t'nod I kniht yllaer uoy oD
.keehc s'dloraH nwod delzzird ecuas otamoT
.enisru dehcterw ,suopmop tahT
.tnemeerga ni deddon miJ "?thgir ,wonk I"
.ybbol eht otni srood elbuod hguorht dna
rehtona eno ta dekool srekrow eciffo ehT
.nwod rehto hcae derats sretcarahc owt ehT
,riahc sih otni kcab deppolf dna
.redluohs sih revo gnuls elfir citsalp a
.seye reh desolc dna pil reh tib
.raeh t'ndluow edis rehto eht no raguoc eht gnipoh
.suoiciled sllems hcnul ruoy ,yas tsum I"
.doof tseb eht thguorb ardnaS syadsendeW no tsael tA
.nirg yhtoot a dehsalf miJ ".iled
.tnialpmoc a ekam ot ekil dluow I"
,draeh evah yam uoy sA
.llaw eht revo gnikop elzzum derruf revlis eht gniciton ton
sreward ksed eht fo eno denepo raguoc ehT
tius depirts-nip yerg sih dehtooms flow ehT
.won thgir yrgnuh ylbirret si hciwdnas taht fo renwo eht erus m'I" ,delbmurg ehS
.gab sih fo tuo hciwdnas a gnillup elihw
.setameciffo sih ecaf ot gninrut
".drac ynapmoc eht no ti egrahc dna
,lufhtuom rehtona levohs ot kcab gninrut
nihtiw morf gnitsorf maercrettub htiw seikooc ragus edamemoh eht fo lufdnah a koot dloraH
.eugnot s'miJ no decnad llits sbreh dna secips fo noitanibmoc ehT
.enola erew yeht erus ekam ot moor eht dnuora dekool eh sa
"?yrgnuh uoY !dloraH yeH" ,lufreehc a htiw llaw eht dednuor eh ,elcibuc sih fo tuo spets wef a gnikaT
.deppord waj s'flow ehT ".wol siht
.gnizzub fo seires a tuo gniyrc dna mrala eht ffo gnittes ,05:11 ot 94:11 morf deknilb
elims yhtoot rehtona ffo gniwohs
.kcatta rieht pots ot elbanu saw tub srenetsaf latem fo egarrab gnimocni eht ta dettaws eH
,elbirret sa saw doof eht eruS
.ylimaf eht otni deirram ehs--ehS"
.hciwdnas taem dekoms naem a sekam teerts eht ssorca iled eht draeh ev'I tuB
.emityna ,ereht ni doof ruoy erots ot eerf leeF"
.uoy htiw laed ot sah reven eh os egdirf inim a sah eneG ,eruS
yadot wohs t'ndid tidnab hcnul eht yppah erew yeht fi erusnu
,drawrof denael ardnaS
.sekacpuc detrossa fo reniatnoc citsalp a ot txen elbat eht no tas
.ylimaf arolF dna snreF ekaF eht ot rebmem wen a emoclew ot erusaelp ym syawla s'tI"
,elcibuc ytpme s'miJ dessap yeht emit yreve deralg eciffo eritne ehT YADIRF # "?pit gib
,dekcilf srae s'dloraH "?hO"
.hguorht daeh reh dekop nageM dna denepo srood ybbol ehT
nwod kcab tas ardnaS ".no
,deunitnoc miJ ,rood rehto eht ot gnitnioP
hgih pu morf dehctaw nus ehT
.flow eht ot hgis yppah a thguorb
,sgnixif eht lla dna ecuas eht elbuod ,eseehc eht elbuod ,taem eht elbuod
.duola ti daer dna
.ria eht ni sdnah reh werht ehS
,llot lleb nmelos a htiw ruoh eht emihc ot nageb lepahc nwot ehT
.selcibuc laudividni rieht ni ylteiuq yawa deldduh ffats rehto eht fo tsom dna
.ssecorp eht ni hcrib eht revo gnilppot
,nroc htiw dewolfrevo reniatnoc citsalp knip ehT
.llaw elcibuc s'dloraH revo pu esor raeb nworb a fo daeh gnirebmul eht
sessalg reh ffo koot enilef ehT ".miJ ,kooL"
ezalg elom ylevol a ni
;eno egdod ot hcrib ekaf a dniheb dekcud dloraH
.sevlehs ytpme eht dnuora detrad seye siH
.nageM iH" .miJ ta devaw
.ksa ot ruovaf a evah I"
.egdirf leets sselniats a dna
.aneleY ot seigolopa tsepeed yM
retnuoc eht dniheb nexiv ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,eciffo niam eht otni ksed sih morf tuo dellor dloraH "!oN ,haG"
.hcnul wen a em redro dna teerts eht ssorca iled eht ot nur uoy ekam I erofeb
.potksed ruoy pu gnittes gnihsinif tsuj m'I"
...llew ,hA" .snikreP ardnaS
,yttiw eb tsum maet selas eht
,deworran seye s'miJ
.miJ detuohs "!enoyreve rof ytrap azzip a reffo I"
.daeh sih detlit flow ehT
.elbat eht no stsif sih demmals miJ ".aneleY
.hteet sih hguorht delworg miJ ".dloraH"
,yad krow eht fo flah tsal eht hguorht reffus ot gnivah morf detartsurF
"?ereh tuo gnilley eht lla s'tahW"
.deffuh eh sa llef dna esor sredluohs siH
.yldneirf oot gnileef ton s'ehs tub ,uoy ecudortni d'I"
,smlif nretseW cissalc devol-tseb sih fo eno neeb syawla dah
tae ot gniog saw eh sehcnul esoht lla neht
.snalp ruo tuoba togrof I ,yrros m'I"
.hcuoc sih no tuo dehcterts dna
,ksed eht no stsif reh demmals dna dnuora nups ardnaS ".hciwdnas
.pu tohs sdnah s'flow ehT "!oN"
.gniod erew sbuc reh woh deksa dna
nepo gnuws moor eht fo dne eht ta rood ehT
,ria eht deffins flow ehT ".dloraH yeH"
htaerb peed a koot ehs
.ruot eht eunitnoc s'tel os ynomerec eht ta uoy ot flesmih ecudortni ll'eH