.lla retfa em sdeen ehS
.kcab gnimoc peek I .tsisrep I llits tuB
tisiv I nehw tuB
.wonk I dna swonk ehS .ylwols yrev
,lirpA fo tser eht rof
.teop eht yb daeR
.em devol tserof eht dna
.erah dliw a hctac ot gniyrt sa  sseltiurf sa eb dluow
.niap eht gnisae fo sepoh eht ni tfel si tahw deef I  .retaw gnirb I
.seert gnillems-teews fo sevorg hguorht sexof desahc dnA
.nrut yreve ta em ta kcab setib ehs tub ,reh tcetorp I
.yawa tpews neeb dah hsurb eht retfa dlot saw I
.elddim yrev eht ni neerg thgirb fo kceps elgnis a rof evaS
.skoob daer-ot fo draoh sih morf gnidaer ton s’eh nehw ,seirots setirw dna semag sekam ohw
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot
.wed gninrom ylrae eht ni sehcnarb reh no gnuws I nehw srebmemer ehS
.denetsil syawla ehs
.em ees ot dalg si ehs syad emoS
,tserof eht evol I
.rebmemer ot reh detnaw I
meop a evah ew yadoT
...dezilaer I neht tuB
.syawla ,snetsil ehs dnA
,ylwolS .gniyd si ehS
,”tseroF“   yojne esaelP
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb ”tseroF“ saw sihT
em tuoba tlef ehs woh rettam oN
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.detaefed reh gniees fo ynoga eht deraps saw I
,relevart wollef ruoy
.kcab emoc I yhw t'nsi siht tuB
.won efas si ehs reh llet ot yrt I
.eybdoog tuohtiw evael dluow ehs yhw dnatsrednu ton did I
.yromem ym ni hsiruolf dluoc seert reh taht oS
.egap yrruFoS sih no dnuof eb nac smeop sih fo erom dna
.enim dna ekas reh roF
.em evol ton seod tserof eht tub
.ereh em tnaw ton seod ehS
niaga gnileef taht esahc oT
.htnoM yrteoP ot uoy gnimoclew
.ot desu yeht sa raf sa og t'nod stoor reH  .em raeh t'now ehS
mrywkooB irikeneN yb meop a
.ytuaeb reh gniyojne tneps ev'I emit eht fo lla llacer I
.reh ni eert tsal eht morf llaf fael tsal eht ees ot raeb ton dluoc I
tserof eht devol I
.ytinummoc eht morf retirw a yb meop a uoy gnidaer eb ll’ew
.krab daed dna selbmarb saw tserof eht dnuof dna retaw ym htiw tnew I yad enO
.I sa raf sa gnirutnev morf srehto tpeK .ffo reh dellaw ev'I
.tliw ot gnitrats era egnirf retuo eht no seert ehT
.teop eht yb daer
.ssel gnits seltten eht os ,siht wonk I
.tisiv I nehw seirots llet I  .pleh t'nseod tI
.ni teg ot yletarepsed deirt I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.deid ehs nehw ereht ton saw I  .liava on ot tuB
.truh dna yrgna saw I emit gnol a rof dnA
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,yadirF dna yadsendeW yrevE
.reh fo tfel si tahw tcetorp tsum ehS
.hcaer fo tuo tey tub esolc syawlA
,moc.irikenen.www no
.dnik ym swonk ehS
.doog naht syad dab erom eb lliw ereht wonk I