.eeffoc a tnaw yllanoisacco dluow dna ,won rednetrab a
,su saw taht tsaeb eht dellik eW .revo s'tI
.nwodhcuot gninniw emag eht erocs
.tuo nworht yltpmorp saw neht dna
tsuj dluoc I thguoht I
.pu ti dewollof ylkciuq rekceB
,revo gnilppot ot esolc ylsuoregnad nettog d'yeht nehW
pu dehsaw ruoy fo yna
.daeh sih koohs neht dna deddon ydoC ".rab
.gniht eruS" .mih dniheb
su fo htob fo erac ekat ot reh rof saw ti drah woh dnatsrednu t'ndluoc uoY
.erom ti desu ohw rettam t'nseoD
.retsemes eht rof rehtruf yna
.slewot ym yawa dekcap I ,mU"
.tuo gnitteg morf sgniht peek ot yrt ot tsuj
kcabretrauq gnitrats sa niw eno sih tog eH
was enoyrevE .enoyreve tub ,su morf tsuj toN
.reh rof tuo hctaw yllaer dluohs I"
,deksa dna retnuoc eht tsniaga kcab sih depmuls flow ehT
meht ot resolc tlef reven ev’I dna
.efil ym ni tac ylno eht er'uoy wonk uoY
.rof gnikool saw eh tahw dnuof eh
.edis sih ta pu gnimoc
.edisni ragus fo tnuoma lauqe tsomla
taht wenk tsuj eh ,oN
.eciov sih ni ssenrettib emos htiw deksa eh
.dleif eht otno tuo pets reve
"!ti did uoY !ti did uoY !ti did uoY"
.selim fo sderdnuh yb detarapes eb ot tuoba erew yeht hguoht nevE
.retfa ti dewollof bos tfos a tub
dna drawrof llab eht hsup ot deganam eh
.tib elttil a eganamorcim ot deen did ehs hguoht neve
,kcab dedlof srae enipul siH
"?efil ym fo yad gnikcuf yreve
.noitcif yrruf trohs gnitirw si
.flow eht ta regnif a gnitniop
htiw ssalg ekil delkcarc ssarg ehT  etoyoC triD yb
,tuo deirc rekceB dna
tbuod on eb d'ereht os
.erus rof roirp thgin eht tub
.tey seitnewt ruo fo tuo neve ton er’eW
.flesmih rof spuc citsalp der owt tuo gnillup
.rekceB pu gnikaw tuohtiw
dluoc eh sa drah sa ti dekcuhc dna gum sih debbarg eh os
?sgnileef ruoy tuoba pu nepo ot tnaw uoy nehw siht sI ,hO“
,gum sih fo sdrahs eht sdrawot deppets ydoC
,selcric ni dnuora nups yehT .smra sih otni
".revetahw tub ,uoy htiw gniyats si rewolb ruf eht ecnis edart riaf a saw ti taht dias moM"
.meht fo owt eht neewteb spu-pils lauxes ynam oot ydaerla erew erehT
ecnahc ym pu evag I"
yeht nehw did hsoJ dna hciR woh ekiL
,htaerb peed a koot ydoC
,seye sih fo tuo dnas eht debbur ydoC
dna dnalsi nehctik eht tsniaga ylralimis dedlof ydob s'rekceB ".no
.nwod dna spu htiw ,yzarc gnikcuf neeb s’tI
"?siht retfa sdneirf eb ot tnaw llits d'uoY"
,laidroc sgniht tpek dah rehtom siH
"—uoy rof nedloG CU ta eb ot
,dehgual htob yehT
efil s'rekceB fo edaced a
.htiw nigeb ot ti did eh dab tlef eh dna
,derepsihw rehtnap eht "?ydoC"
,maet sih ,emag eht gninniw etipseD
loohcs ruoy :decifircas ew gnihtyreve
.siht dennalp dah eh
.sraet hguorht detuohs rehtnap eht "!seY" "?—uoy dluoW
.ecniw ot ton tseb sih did ydoC dna
flah wenk uoy ekil
",snaeb ruoy fo lla peek nac uoY
neddih su peek ot tnaw t'nod I
".puc a ot eerf er'uoY"
,worb sih deworruf ydoC
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
"?riaf smees ti os tneve txen eht rof rehto eht etivni ot evah ew ,gnihtemos od ot tuo eno etivni ew fi
dna mom sih fo esnefed ni emoc ot rehtnap eht rof ylno
,hguoht lla ti hguorhT
,dad sih yb oga keew a gnissik thguac neeb d'yehT
.taht erofeb gnol detrats skcarc eht tub
",rehtie uoy etah t'nod I"
ydoC dna taht ta delkcuhc meht fo htoB
.kcab dloh ot hcum oot emaceb stcnitsni rieht litnu selims ediw otno gnidloh htob ,tem seye riehT
.meht fo htob yb dootsrednu neeb evah dluow ekoj eht dna
.seilppus nehctiK
,ti fo lla hguorht edis ruoy ta deyats I dnA"
.desolc ti gnikcol dna hctal eht fo dloh gnibbarg
,tsrif ta decnivnocnu ylgnimees
esuaceb reh detneser tsuj uoY"
"?tuo rekam eeffoc eht ekat uoy did lleh eht yhw ekiL
.ecaf gnivas tuoba tnamada syawla
.htrof dna kcab daeh sih koohs ydoC
.redluohs s'xe sih otni derettum ydoC ,bos a hguorhT
.teef sih no nwod kcab mih tas ydoC
.tniop sih ni gid ot tsuj mra sih gnitator ,dias eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,noisnet eht fo emos
,rehtnap eht ecaf ot denrut ydoC
,flesmih rof hcum kooc t'ndid eH
.sehsid eht fo flah neve dna
.tekcaj namrettel nwo sih ni mih sdrawot gninnur rehtnap eht decaf dna
,pu dekool rekceB ".uoy
.erom rof deksa evah t'ndluoc eH
,taht dootsrednu ydoC
dnoces a rof tuhs wam sih gnipeek enilef eht
,htaerb peed a koot eh ,pu gnidliub snoitome hcum os htiW
.elpoep teem ot klat ot woh erus yllaer ton m’I .repeerc gnikcuf
,gninrom eht ni ylrae ytterp
.teiuq deniamer yeht
.gniog tpek tsuj rehtnap eht tub
gnittilps er'ew kniht uoY"
.ylkaew dettimda eh
,yawa ti dellup eh ,yletaidemmI
,dleif ytpme na ni neve dna ,nepo os
,haeY" .denihw rekceB
,redluohs sih dehcnip noitom ehT
.ylsseltneler em dekcom yehT
.snac ados fo skcats rednu gnihtyna
.lufetarg erom elttil a eb dluoc uoy ,wonk uoY"
.enod s'tI ?gnithgif
,renroc eht dnuora emac rehtnap eht sa noos sa ,hguone erus dnA
litnu ylsselerac potretnuoc eht otno reffub repap eht gnissot
,won sraey ekil tlef ti
,syawyna emag eht ot emoc evah dluow yeht thguoht dah eH
"?rab nwo ruoy evah uoy t'noD
.yltsenrae rehtnap eht ta dekool
.elzzum s'flow eht fo edis eht nwod nar sraeT ".laed
.edam neeb dah sekatsiM
saw xob tsal ehT ".gniht
"?owt eht erapmoc dluoc uoy taht tuo krow neve
.did ehs sa drah sa mih dekrow ehs yhw
.moorhtab eht ot revo srae sih dekcilf rekceB
,duht a htiw ti otni tnew waptoof siH
.ekas s’rehtnap sih rof ti otno dloh ot deirt eh tub
dna erofeb thgin eht rehtegot emoh delbmuts yeht yhw saw taht ,esruoC
,dedda eh ,noitautis eht pu nethgil ot dna ,dias eh
saw sihT      .reveroF ".reveroF"
,flesreh pleh t’ndluoc ehs wenk ydoC
.enihcam eeffoc gnikcuf nwo sih yub dluoc rekceB tub ,yttep
.yaw eritne eht redluohs sih otni delzzun kcen mraw siH
.uoy esol ot tnaw reve t’nod I tub
.sgniht eseht tuoba yllausu er'uoY"
,no evom ot gniog erew yeht fi
hguoht ,oga htnom a saw tI .did eH ".uoy
,taht tuoba thgir erew uoY“
.reliart eht pu esolc ot rekceB dna ydoC htob koot tI
mih detnaw eh yhw saw sihT .ediw seye
.buc a fo slliks lanoitazinagro eht dah rekceB ,sgarb eh sa trams sa roF
d'eh gnihtemos ,draobpuc eht tsniaga kcab sih denael ydoC
nwod hsauqs ot deirt
.ylluferac rehtegot seceip eht gnilip
;nav gnivom eht otni deffuts
.erom ti desu ohw rettam t'ndiD
.sucum pu detrons eh
.emit gib ti ni deppets eh wenk eh ,htuom sih tfel sdrow eht sa nevE .detpurretni eH
.selur gnikcuf driew ynam ooT
.kcalb sih deppis tsuj rehtnap eht
.reippah eb t'ndluoc eh
,yas ot saw eugnot s’ydoC fo pit eht ffo gniht tsrif yrev ehT
”reveroF reveroF reveroF“   yojne esaelP
.maet a evah dluow ytinummoc taht ton
.enil eht otni thgiarts tnew dna mra sih rednu llabtoof eht dekcut eh erehw eno eht
.ti gniyas rof buc gnikcuf a ekil tlef yletaidemmi dna
.lluf sretrauq eerht tuoba ti dellif ydoC dna
.yug dab eht saw eh woh ni dellird t'ndah gnilesnuoc egairram fo shtnom eht ekil
,ereh teg ot hcum os tsol ev’I
taht yrujni llabtoof eht
.thgirla eb ll'tI .trams dna evitcartta er'uoY
nehw ot desu nettog
taht gnihtemos ,redluohs sih degguls yllufyalp rehtnap ehT ".efil
.daeh sih fo kcab eht ot wap
,egelloc ni llabtoof gniusrup flesmih ees t'ndid eH
”reveroF reveroF reveroF“
"?rehtona eno gnitah pu dne ew did nehW"
.em no taehc ot yako saw ti taht leef ot desoppus t’nerew uoY"
.loohcs rof etats evael ot noisiced s’rekceB htiw smret ot emoc yllanif d’eh tub
.rentrap sih rof pu dnats ot meht gnisol fo diarfa oot saw eh dna rekceB
.rehtona eno revo gnilley tsuj erew yeht tub
.ti htiw hguorht og d'eh ,tsol dah maet rieht fi nevE
,smra sih dessorc ydoC
,elims a no tup ,denrut flow ehT
,mih detpurretni eh taht doog saw tI
",gnicnad ekil uoY ?sbulc eht fo eno kcip uoy t'naC
.ti otni eeffoc erots rallod
terces ni rehtegot siht gniod neeb ev'ew
?srab ruo pu yvvid dluohs ew ebyaM"
,pu ti thguorb reveN
,ekarD ,dneirf tseb sih htiw lacisyhp nettog neve d'eH
.ylimaf ruoy er'yehT .dnuora emoc ll'yehT" .yletaidemmi
,elzzum sih no llits elims
.deb eht fo edis sih ot gnihcoocs
revewoh yats nac uoy taht syas moM"
.eromyna hcum os toN
.regnif s'rehtnap eht otno
.thgiarts gnidnats ,dias rekceB
.xofnogard reppad eht
elihw retnuoc eht no gum sih tas ydoC
,smadA rekceB ecnaL"
,taht htiW .drow taht saw
",seicnelaviuqe eslaf tuoba klaT
dna seye s'dneirfyob sih otni pu dekool eH
.gniddon erofeb yllufthguoht pu seye sih detfil ydoC ".elpoep
.dehgis eh sa daeh sih koohs eh dna
,dehgis htob yehT
”—uoy erofeb taht od ot tnaw t’ndiD
dna guh thgit a otni mih dellup eH
,revo lla dessorc gnieb erew seniL
.esnopser a fo thguoht eh sa
,roirefni saw ffuts paehc eht taht gninialpmoc syawla saw eH
.sgniht tuoba gniklat ekil
.dnuorg eht drawot elzzum sih htiw dias eh
,detpurretni ydoC
",ereht tuo yaw ym krow yllautneve nac I
",flesreh gnitroppus elihw
.won sraey owt rof
.rewohs ylbaborp dluohs I"
.kcab derruf trohs a no dnal ot ylno
ylimaf ym pu gnirb erad uoy t'noD"
derettahs tI HSARC
***** .reveroF ".reveroF" "?reveroF"
,oga edaced a tsuj toN
.trats eht ta erew yeht neht ecalp retteb a ni tub ,detsuahxe
.rehtnap eht ot drawrof gnippets ,egnellahc eht detpecca ydoC
”,sknahT .won od I naht
",tnemtraped SC gnipoleved a sah krapneerG fo ytisrevinU draeh I kniht I"
,nelarD yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
".retto taht htiw gnipeels yb yawa lla ti worht ot uoy rof ylno
,erac t'ndluow maet eht taht mih dlot rekceB ,esruoc fO
?ecnahc a meht evig t’ndiD“
,yppah saw eh hguoht dna
.ti edecnoc ot tuoba saw I ,yllautcA"
motpmys a tsuj saw taht tub ,rekceB ,hsalf sweN
.taht od dluoc eh woh dootsrednu reven eH
,deerga rekceB ,ssenlufhsab emos htiW ".etad
.htiw nigeb ot gniht sih reven saw gniklat tub
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.taht mih tfel rekceB ,esruoc fO
kcom dluow sdneirf s’flow eht erehw semiT
,syawyna pukcab ym erew yehT
taht won evah ot dedeen syawla
?gniod ew er'tahW"
.deticxe siht tog eh nehw niatnoc t'ndluoc eh gnihtemos
.yag saw eh taht dnuora tnew sromur tsrif eht nehw
"?ereh steg moM emit eht yb enog eb ll'uoY
.ria eht otni tuo wap a werht eh dna
,ekops yllanif enilef eht ,sdnoces wef a retfA .elihw elttil a
.mir eht revo eeffoc emos llips ot hguone kciuq rehtnap eht ta gum sih gnitniop
.ragus dna maerc eht htiw ecnereffid eht etsat t'ndluoc ydoC tub
.tnerappa emoceb ot gnitrats
,deilper eh ",wonk I .wonk I"
.rekam eeffoc a fo kcal eht saw
eeffoc fo spird eht ylno
.sdneirf llabtoof resol dekaep-loohcshgih
.yllausac detpurretni rekceB
.rehtie taht ekil eb ot su tnaw t'nod I
erew sgniht nehw neve ,rehtegot
meht evig neve t’ndid uoY !em yb
I dna ,uoy was I ,sknird elpuoc a retfa oS .haeY"
.dehgis eh sa elzzum s'flow eht fo tuo delahxe ria yduolc fo ffup A
.uoy etah yllautca t’nod I —t'nod I"
s'nehw ,kceB ,zeeJ"
dna dleif eht ssorca detrad tac eht sa emit ni flesmih ecarb t'ndid tsomla eH
tsethgils eht leef t'nod
?uoy no detaehc I esuac
,dedda eh ,nworf a ni kcuts llits saw rehtnap eht deciton eh nehw tub ,dias eh
.syawyna sredluohs sih deggurhs tub
llits ew era yhW
.sdnats ytpme eht fo ecnelis eiree eht morf tuo gnar eciov A "!ydoC"
.pleh dna yats nac I sseug I"
.no evom ot teg yllanif ew dna
"?reveroF" ,deksa dna
,ti tuoba thguoht eh nehw dna
,deksa dna rekceB ot kcab denrut neht eH
,daeh sih koohs tsuj rekceB
taht elur driew eht ro
"?gnihtyreve s'tahT"
raeh ot detnaw eh llA
.gnidloh saw eh puc citsalp eht gnilpmid swalc ,ecnats sih denethgiarts rehtnap ehT
,syawyna yas ot ecin gnihton saw erehT
!uoy gninodnaba rof ylimaf nwo ruoy etah uoy
.llah eht otni tuo gnilbmuts enoemos fo dnuos eht draeh eh sa tsuj gnillif saw top ehT
nwot kcufmub siht ni deyats dna—"
.dniheb mih gnivael
na ni gniruop erofeb maerc fo tnuoma ytfeh a dedda flow ehT
,daeherof sih revo wap a htiw dias rekceB
.esuap gnol a saw erehT
.ssem ykcits siht edam
.kcab sih dniheb dias gnihtyreve
.sdnats ytpme eht drawot kool tub pleh t’ndluoc eh
.dnim sih no noitseuq rehtona dah enilef eht tub
gnivom eb t'ndluow dna noisivid eht ni tsal saw
.romuh fo esnes rieht teg t’ndid uoY .oohoob ,hO“
,eralg a fo tib elttil a htiw pu dekool eh dna
".kaeps ot moor yna
.raey a fo kceh eno saw tI
.ylthgit kcab dezeeuqs rekceB
"?ynnep eht ot nwod lla ti detaluclac
.redluohs dab ym htiw nevE
paehc sih ni gniruop dna retlif a tuo gnillup ,pu ti tes eH
",syawyna ydaer m'I kniht t'nod I
,suoicilam neeb evah t'ndluow tI
".hguorht tnew I tahw fo
.evas ot tfel saw gnihton
.rab thgiarts a s'tI .rab nwo ym ta knird annog ton m'I"
",ti teg I .on ,haeY"
,redluohs sih no wap a detser rekceB
.t'ndid eh tub ".erofeb
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ffo yaw sih gnilggiw ylluferac
rehtnap eht fo gniddap teiuq eht raeh t'ndid tsomla eH
"?ydaer er'uoy kniht t'noD"
,deppid elzzum enipul s’ydoC ".dnuora
.uoy ni deveileb syawla I
reh dna uoY :esirprus a s'taht ,hO"
.hgis a ni dias eh
.enod ydaerla s'tI"
.shtnom gnimoc eht ni slaem sih fo ytirojam
"?uoy t'nod ,taht od ot ekil od uoy
.maet sih fo troppus elohw eht htiw ti did eh dna
.kcab ruoy dah ekarD nevE
—I“ ,gnidda erofeb desuap eh ”,eromyna
.gnikaeps ydaerla saw eh
.niaga ti tih t'ndluow eh os yaw eht fo tuo tsuj xob eht dehsup eH
dna dnim ot emac thguoht tahT
.ecaf sih ni gnihtyreve gniworht tpeK
dna seitriht ruo ni tsomla er'eW .driew s'tahT
,yltfiws dedda ydoC
,hguoht dootsrednu eh ekil dekool rekceB
os saw ereht —tsuj eW"
.rallod a fo eulav eht dnatsrednu reven dluoc
,tes enirugif gnikcuf s'rekceB otni nar eh fI
.ti thguob I .rekam eeffoc yM"
,no mih derrups revognah gnidnuop ehT
.dnuora gnipeels fo sthguoht dah d’eh ,retto eht erofeb nevE
,elzzum sih fo sedis eht nwod nar sraet nwo siH
.rehtnap sih ot kcab denrut eh dna
.keehc sih ot kcep a htiw gniwollof ,detuohs rekceB "!ti did uoY"
ev'yeht thgif eht
.teef ruoy no kcab teg uoy litnu esuoheraw reh ta boj a uoy teg neve nac ehs ,kceH .tnaw uoy gnol
,ti naem did eh hguohT .dias ydoC
.knis sih revo tsuj
.sdrow sih fo thguoht eh sa esuap elttil a ,detrats ydoC ",oS“
,sevink evisnepxe eht ,rossecorp doof eht ,rednelb eht dnatsrednu dluoc eH
,tib a deretlaf elims siH
.gniyats saw rekam eeffoc eht taht tniop a ekam ot fi sa
.segamad rof kcehc ot tsuj eno elgnis yreve tuo llup mih evah ot erus eb d'eh
,kcab detuohs ydoC "!eciohc
.sdrow sih eveileb ylurt t'ndid tub ,dias eh
.did yeht dna uoy troppus dluow maet ruoy uoy dlot I"
dna derac eh taht wonk mih tel ot hguone saw ti tuB
.kcab gniod ydoC detah eh
,thgin tsal deneppah tahw em llet esaelP"
,ylyls dennirg rekceB
.eeffoc dedeen eH
.rab a ni enola dnats tub gnihtyna od ot detnaw adnik tsuj
.pihw a ekil gnippans liat
,esuoh eht sdrawot dekool ydoC ".gnihtyreve
taht hguone llew wenk yehT
.ecalp ni dekcol ti litnu rood eht nwod dellor dna epor llup a debbarg hcaE
”.reeuq uoy gninrut ot em esucca yeht emit htdnasuoht eht retfa
?taht od uoy od yhW" .deworruf worb
?thgir ,erofeb enoyna htiw pu dekooh yllaer reven ev’uoy sseug I"
.hsoJ dna hciR ekil eb ot su tnaw t'nod I"
,tsehc sih revo mra na dedlof eH
em detiolpxe mom ruoY
.kcurt dezis-moor a otni dezeeuqs
uoy dna ,uoy ot esolc eb ot tsuj
.tihs paehc eht s'tI" "—ti sI"
?rekam eeffoc eht tuB
.hserf llits dnuow eht
.yltcerroc laeh ot demees reven
.desopmoc erom dekool eh litnu eson sih revo wap a gnipiw ,desuap rekceB
deveiler hguoht tahT
dna top eht debbarg tsuj eH
,gnuts yeht hguoht dna
.rekceB sdrawot tuo ti gnidloh erofeb gum sih otni ti deruop
.sexob eht tuoba noitseuq a hcum os t'nsaw tI
,redluohs derujninu s'ydoC degguls rekceB
.dleif llabtoof ytpme eht otno koot ydoC petstoof yreve
yats ot snoitatcepxe riafnu ynam os dah tsuj eW .ylimaf ym dna
.eciohc s'flow eht yb detlover yllauqe
saw tI .namow lufwa
.rehtegot yats ot gniog ylurt
saw tI .detrilf I"
,ekilbuc saw sloohcs egnahc ot mih gniksA
.esion fo tol a ekam dluow taht gnihtemos naht rehtar
,pu gniworg emos koot tI
,gum sih ta dekool rekceB
.won rof reppoH ehT evah nac uoY .tib a rof tsuJ
.thgin eht otni gnidaf ydaerla
”.sknahT .ylbaborp ,haeY“
.xob eht fo pot eht revo epat eht hguorht nar eh ,walc sih htiW
.emit siht ton sseuG
.etad reporp a dah ew evah reven
,niagA .won etal ooT
.dnuora emoc ot evah yehT
uoy erew rO .su saw taht recnac eht fo
evah t'nod uoY .gnitrilf tsuj
revo dekool ydoC
.gniht ym adnik si reppoH ehT"
.potretnuoc dnalsi eht fo pot no xob a ta
,yrtnap eht sdrawot yliggorg devom rekceB
.gum nekorb sih revo walc a decart ydoC
,dias dna htrof dna kcab daeh sih koohs eh ,tuo flesmih gninethgiartS
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb ”reveroF reveroF reveroF“
deb eht evael ot tsuj niap eht erob eh ,llitS
erew yeht won dna
.kcurt eht ni saw gnihtyreve
,saw tih tsal taht dab woh ees ot enoyna tnaw t'ndid eH
.ytliug elttil a leef tub pleh t'ndluoc eh
,puc sih tuo dleh rehtnap ehT
"?lewot ruoy esu I fi dnim uoy dluoW
,gnihton dias flow eht fi sa deunitnoc tsuj eH
.langis gnorw eht ffo evig yllatnedicca ot tnaw t’ndid eh ecnis yllaicepse
.yawa pets a koot
dnabsuh-xe —dnabsuh siH
.pohstaews gnikcuf reh ni sraey rof
,taht ot dnopser ot woh wonk t’ndid ydoC
.nehctik eht ot yaw eht lla gnidael draobdrac fo ezam a saw ereht ,esruoc fO
sevorp thgin tsal kniht I ,gnihtyna fI"
,gnitrilf s’rekceB
,htiw detrats enilef eht sa tsuj pu tnew srae siH
!kceB ,gniht gnikcuf emas eht toN— " "—dad yM"
.ti yub did ydoC tub
a ekil gnikool ,renroc eht ni dnats saw od dluoc I llA
.kcab dedlof srae sih
,tnaem evah dluoc eh taht sgniht ynam os erew ereht hguohtla
;hguorht tnew ew tahw
.eciov sih ni eci emos htiw tohs ydoC
.erofeb uoy deppots reveN"
,ni sdrow erom teg ot deirt eH .enod saw ydoC tub
.krow ot su rof erusserp hcum
,moor eht revo emac ecnelis eiree nA
:tniop emos ta gnirudne eb ot desu tI
rof ereht ti dleh dna redluohs sih no wap a detser rekceB
,ti tuoba dab tlef eh esruoc fO "!esromer fo tib
.rehto hcae morf ecnatsid emos esu ylbaborp dluoc ew tuB
.tnemtnioppasid sih pu revoc ot daeh sih fo kcab eht ot wap a gnihctarcs ,dias ydoC
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no
,redluohs sih tuoba nialpmoc d’eh erehw semiT
.sruoh rof rab eht ta saw I
dna evren a ekirts ot demees tahT ”.ecnahc a
,sediseB .tuo og uoy nehw sdneirf llabtoof ruoy htiw syawla er’uoY
"?si ydaerla ti naht drawkwa erom
",gniralb cisum eht htiw sbulc eht ta sedud no tih ot drah s'ti
.don prahs a evag dna
,oN" ,deunitnoc
.knurd elihw emoh klaw ot reisae ,resolc saw tI
.mih detpurretni lleb s’enihcam eeffoc eht fo gnid a tub
"!meht htiw knird oG
”,saw reve ti naht esrow ti edam ylbaborp ehs ,lleH
.seye s'flow eht revo pu tliub sraeT
.gnir loohcs hgih sih tuo dellup
pihsnoitaler rieht gnittup trats ot evah ot gniog saw eh
.tseb eht rof saw ti os
.dedecnoc eh ",eno retrams eht neeb syawla ev'uoY
tellub a dah syawla rekceB ,esruoc fo tub
elpoep emos esuaceB" .rebmahc eht ni
a otni selzzum rieht dekcol yehT
,mih dniheb tuoba dehsal liat s'rekceB
,gniyas ,kcab eht tsniaga swalc sih depparw flow ehT
,dias ydoC ",emit eht lla em fo tnorf gnikcuf ni thgir ti od d'uoY"
,terces a ti peek ot drah os deirt ydoC
,sgnineve etal dekrow llits ydoC
naht uoy rof erom enod s’moM ?uoy erad woH"
"?detareb gnieb saw I nehw knirhs eht ot noitnetta gniyap ylno
.eenk a otno nwod tog dna ,tekcop sih otni nwod dehcaer
etoyoC triD wolloF
,sreggoL krapneerG eht
.llaf eht ni nedloG CU ot gniog uoy htiw
ecaf ym ni nworht taht gnivah pots yllanif nac I os ereh teg neeuq eci gnikcuf eht
.enod morf raf saw rekceB tub
.rehto hcae etah t'nod ew
dna sraey wef a eb ylno ll'tI
.emag eht retfa dleif eht no mih teem ot
htam eht did woH
.draeh eb dluoc knis eht otno gnilddup
.ti rof tluaf ta saw eh taht wonk ot truh ti dna
,ylhsipeehs nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon ydoC
.meht detsurt eh taht wonk ot dedeen tsuj
kcuts taht elpoep ylno eht erew yehT"
,hguoht drah eb ll'tI"
nwo ruoy saw tahT"
.gnimoc saw thgif gnidnepmi na
.reppoH ehT pu evig ot gnitnaw ton ,tuo detniop eh
,sdrow ykahs ni deksa ydoC
,ti thguob tsrif eh nehw skcub ytnewt ylno saw tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sraet eht yawa epiw ot seye sih ot swap sih tup dna
.laiceps tlef eno siht
.reppoH ehT ot og reve yldrah uoY"
,mih rof gnihtyna evah t'ndluow eh thguoht tsomla d'eH
,elbissop sa ylteiuq sa steehs eht pu werht eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.eb ot dah ti naht drawkwa erom gnihtyna ekam t'ndid tub
,ekops eh ,did eh sA
,ereht t'nsi rehto eht erus ekam ot emit fo daeha srab llac yeht erehw gniht ehT ?trap hcihW" .rekceB ecaf ot denrut eh
stnecs rieht ni gnikat ,ssik etanoissap gnol
",neppah yllautca t'ndid
,rettiwT no elbuort gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
,elbat eht tsniaga puc sih deppals rekceB
sehtolc htiw dellif ylno yllufknaht
.ti dias neve eh erofeb pu saw gnihtemos wenk ydoC dna
mih hguorht was rekceB
taht rof sexob dnuora gnigguls saw eh nehw hcum sa ylraen toN
.dnuorg eht ffo neet rehto eht gnitfil kcoj eht
.srepap eht dengis eW
.esuoheraw eht ni stfihs thgin etal gnikrow saw eh nehw ti thguob d'eH
,eromyna eciov nwo sih raeh neve t'ndluoc eH
,keehc sih ot eugnot sih dekcilc rehtnap ehT
.driew ti ekam t'noD"
.edis sih ta htrof dna kcab gnikcilf liat keels
,pu ti thguorb rekceB
dna ydoC fo tuo trons a tog tahT ".hsoJ
",siht ekil dne ot ti tnaw t'ndid tsuj I"
neeb ev'tsum tI
.retfa gnihtyna yas t’ndid tub
dnif ot elba eb t’ndluow dnabsuh sih wenk eh esuaceb ksed s’rehtnap eht pu naelc dluow ydoC erehw semit
.eromyna deb eht fo edis sih t'nsaw ti ,lleW
nehctik eht otni deklaw eh nehw deciton eh gniht tsrif yrev ehT
,elzzum s’rekceB tilps elims naem A
dna ylsuovren teef sih delffuhs rekceB ".won
,dias ydoC ",enim s'tI
.deb sih tsuj saw tsuj ti woN
.syawyna trapa gnillaf saw tuo dennalp dah eh hceeps gib eht esuac
ekoj a tsuj gnieb spots tI
,evig ot drah saw tnemilpmoc ehT ".tey
saw dnim s’ydoC ot emac taht gniht tsrif ehT ".tnerappa
.llah eht ni tuo gniyal xob a otni kconk ot ylno
,revo neeb ev'thgim siht thguoht eH
noridirg eht fo enil etihw hcaE
.gnihtyreve s'taht kniht I"
,kcab dedlof srae s'rehtnap ehT "?pu tilps
"?leef ot desoppus I saw woH—"
sa potretnuoc eht tsniaga deknalc cimarec ehT
.yug doog a er'uoY .kceB ,nom’C"
,mih ot ti did flow eht nehw ti ekil t'ndid eh hguoht neve
s'ti os suoivbo eht tuo tniop syawlA
"?xob erom eno s'tahW
dna swap sih deppord ydoC
.ot gnidnopser saw eh tahw erus t’nsaw eh
.mih delian yllaer kcab decrof eh klE eht ,gniddap eht lla htiw nevE
saw efil dlo sih sa tsuj mih fo tnorf ni efil wen sih
.ti tnaem yllautca eh
.thgin tsal —tsuj s'ti ,haeY"
!emag eht now uoy dnA
",rehtegot shtnom wef a evah ll'ew tsael tA
dna tnemtneser yna htiw ti ksa t'ndid eH
"—er'uoy em llet t'noD" "—yllautcA"
.emitefil a fo ytinutroppo na si nedloG CU .em rof siht od t'noD"
,detaefed dekool rekceB
eht pu ekam annog erew seldoon degakcap
.tuo eugnot sih kcuts eh dna nworf kcom a otni detsiwt elzzum s'ydoC ".reh
,rekceB morf hgual kaew a tog tahT ".rehto
.mih rof ereht eb syawla dluow
gnir sih deppils eh
,elims-flah a evag rekceB
.dniwnu ot pukooh a dnif
,nedloG CU ot gniog llits saw rekceB fi nevE
,kaeps ot elzzum sih denepo ydoC ".lufetarg
d'eh emit tsal eht ylbaborp saw siht ,kceH
",uoy htiw evol ni yllacitcarp s'ehS
.ria thgin dloc eht dna
.revognah emas eht gnitrops tbuod on
,deunitnoc ydoC ,elkcuhc detraeh-flah a htiw tub
.laed a gib oot ton s'ti os
.seye sih denepo neve eh erofeb taht wenk ydoC
,tuo derettum eh ",hctib a fo noS"
edis eht ot revo dellor mra sih erofeb ti wenk eH
,deksa eh ,tfel rehtnap eht erofeb tub
ti enod d'yeht emit tsrif eht saw tI