.elbuort eht meht devas dna ,denotni ymereJ ”!nemeltneG“
.lemarac gniyub ot dnuora tog t’ndah dna selppa lemarac meht ekam ot tnaem d’eh taht
.yks eht ni sdnalsi eht saw taht ,oN
.noisivelet euqitna na saw erehT
”?ton yhw ,suoegrog nikcuf s’ti ,ereh suoregnad gnihton s’erehT
,efac a neeb evah thgim ni erew yeht gnidliub ehT ”?senob ynam woH
”.nrut s’esle enoemos s’tI .hsuh woN
gniliec detluav hgih eht ffo deohce spets riehT
…ekil tsuj er’yehT“
,deb latipsoh a saw erehT
toof sih pu dekcip tsuj eH
.teerts eht gnicaf wodniw krad eht no
.rood nepo eht ni demaerts thgilnus fo tfahs a dna
.edistuo tresed eht tsap
”.selur eht daer ot keew a ekat dna sexob neetfif ni emoc taht semag yalp ylno elpoep trams dna snorom rof era semag oediv woh tuoba gniklat yad lla dneps yeht erehw murof emos no fo draeh eh taht erehwemos morf ti detropmi ylbaborp eH“
,meht neewteb ni teg ot deirt giarC ”,nwod mlaC“
.ereh ,ecalpyna toN“ ”?ew era erehW“
,sselehtenon ,devom tI
,tahw yb llet ot tnemom a koot tI
,daor devap eht ffo toof eno pets ti tel uoY
.revir peets a ni sevaw gnidnats ekil
.sseug I .rehtegot ti peek...“
.sredluohs sih dehcnuh giarC
”.ecnahc erom ENO uoy evig ll’I os ,yob ,stimil tog ecneitap yM
”!ydaerla detrats teg s’teL“
,ylmlac oot ,ksam eht ni nam eht dias ”,wonk’Y“
,eldnac driht a fo esab eht dnuora gniloop dna dellips kni ,derettacs skoob
,sesol uoy fo eno ylekil erom ehT
.tenalp eht morf nees
.ti dezingocer eh erus ytterp saw eH
.emag draob a tsol eh nehw did syawla eh yaw eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.enod er’uoy nehw ereh eb ll’I
”.hguoht ,esol ew ,taht od eW“
,sdrac fo elip eht ot txen nwod kcab selur eht deppolp eH
”.ti yalp ot emit eht s’woN
toof sih tsniaga tser ot nwolb dah taht fael a yawa dekcik giarC
gnoma dekcut lluks eno ,lwob a ni stiurf emos fo paeh elttil A .seno ddO
”.em ta GNILLEY pots uoy fi era yeht tahw uoy LLET ll’I“
”.dnatsrednu uoy rehtehw ton erac I .os enod evah I“
,ylraelc ees ot elba saw eh gniht tsrif ehT
”.fles nwo ym os yas od I’f ,sdnah etirovaf ym ’a enO .floW eht
meht dnuora dlrow eht tlef yeht dna
,eb tsum sdrac eht os ,sdrac ward dna sdaor eht gnola og ot desoppus er’ew ,kO“
ehT“ .dnah s’giarC pu dleh ylwols moT
.snroht gnimossolb htiw stsirw eht ta deit
.sselitip tub ,lufituaeb ylbissopmi ,ylbidercni
,sdaor eht fo eno nwod devaw eh ”…wonk uoy
?dnah ruoy ni esle gnihtyna tog uoy fI“
,htiw gnilaed nehw tnatropmi saw etilop gnieb taht erehwemos daer dah moT ”.ma’am ,hU
.deretne yeht nehw teef reh ot tog moor niam eht ni namow ehT
”?koobelur eht tuohtiw“ ,dias moT
,gniggas saw foor eht fo noitces A
,taps ymereJ ”,GNIHTON s’tI“
”.revoL eht fo dnaH eht dna ,esirnuS
.dnuorg eht ot evitaler ,ekil“
.elbuort eht mih gnivas ,giarC dias ”,emag a morf gnihtemos ton ,sdrac toraT driew ekil kool eseht ,haeY“
”.doohrobhgien eht ni devil ev’yeht naht regnol ytpme neeb sah esuoh eht dias yehT
.desumanu ylrettu dna wol dna
”?nwod tis ot deen uoy oD ?ko uoy erA“
.aes gnirettilg a ot nwod sllafretaw fo seires a ni
.kcab me‘ ksa I oS .ees’y ,seirots tsohg llet I yhw ksa kloF“
”?koobelur eht evah ,hu ,I“
.der era noitullop thgil yb woleb morf til sduolc yvaeh taht yaw eht ro
,kcabrepap ysatnaf dlo na fo segap eht ekil ega htiw dewolley ,detnirp ylpaehc—koobelur eht hguorht gnifael ,dias ymereJ
”!sgnileef drah oN“
”!wonk uoy ,oot emag a yllanigiro erew sdrac toraT“
ksam eht htiw yug eht naem taht seod“
,moT ta detniop ,deplug eh ”…dna …sdrac eseht dnA“
.nmyh dna esnecni fo daetsni ecaps eht dellif gnosdrib dna srewolfdliW
!pu maet ew snaem taht oS
sdnah fo riap A .meht
.noitpure cinaclov a fo ssenneddus eht htiw pu ekops giarC
.enog erew yeht dnA ”.laed ,ko...“ ”?laeD
”-tub ,ti dnemmocer I yas t’naC
.eson sih nwod raf yllausunu dehsup
,wodniw krad eht nI .pu dekool dna
,floWcaM boR yb ”edistuO tfeL naM htruoF“
erehwyreve neewteb yaw eht no noitcesretni na
,no gnidnats rebmemer dluoc moT taht spets ,spets eerht gnissim erew hcrop eht ot sriats ehT
,sdrac rof dekram secaps revo
.ot elba eb dluohs sduolc naht retsaf gniwolb
.emoh derednaw ecnis gnol dah sretaert ro kcirt tseidwor dna tsedlo eht tub lla hguoht
hguoht ,yrots a llet ot desop’s era seno tseb ehT
noitatibah fo tnanmer ylno ehT
”.ecno ylno tub dna
.ti ssorca bewredips a dah rood tnorf ehT
.noitazilaer s’giarC dna regna s’moT fo daeha yats ot ,dluoc eh sa ylkciuq sa nam deksam eht drawot deppets eh ”!yeH
”…tub ,enif m’I ,lleW“ ”?ko uoY“
htuom sih denepo dna daeh sih kcab werht eh
”.tluaf RUOY s’taht ,thgir eman eht evah t’ndid I fI“ .delwocs moT
rood s’ymereJ morf kcab deppets nooccar ehT
,wonk t’ndid eh taht yas ot tuoba saw moT
.ruf krad sih ni esnet dna ediw erew seye siH
,moor eht ni enola YLLAER er’uoy erus ekam dna
.ffo yaw gnol a derettacs stnalp burcs fo sehctap wef a
”…emoh og ot teg t’nod ew dna
,mroftalp rehtona ot detniop ,devom drows ehT
dna gniliob dna kcalb erew ni sduolc eht dna
.thgil hcrop lanif s’thgin eht ffo dehctiws ymereJ ecno spmalteerts gnirekcilf dna
deplug mussop eht ”,erus m’I“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,meht sdrawot ,draob eht drawot drawrof gninael
.thgilnus noonretfa eht ni esuoh tnacav eht dehctaw yehT
,teerts eht nwod deohce taht duht a htiw tuhs rood tnorf yvaeh ehT
dediced moT taht ssenrednet fo dnik a htiw
.taht wonk t’nod uoY“
,daeh sih kcab detlit mussop ehT
.niaga llebrood eht desserp nooccar ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.llew sa ,egacbir rieht hguorht tresed eht ees dluoc uoy neht dnA
”.rof gnikool er’ew tahw saw taht“
,nottub eht desserp dah giarC nehw ffo enog dah llebrood eht fi raeh t’ndluoc eH
,flesti til eldnac eht niagA
,seloheye elbadaernu
!yeH“ .kcab derepsihw dribgnikcom ehT ”.t’now I“
.yob ,yalp ruoy edam uoY“
”.tnemtnetnoc seil yaw taht dna
,cisum ylhtraenU .gnas dna
,yerg dna nworb nmutua etal fo sedahs ,gnillor yltneG
,sdaor fo kcip tsrif ekaT“
,nehctik eht ot pu meht thguorb eh nehw ,dias dah yemereJ
”.nihton ton s’ti
,denworf giarC ”…lleW“
”?thgir ,emag eht snaem eH“
.enog saw ehs erus saw eh nehw ,giarC dias
”,uoy erofeb eciohc eht fo uoy llet ot ecalp ym si tI“
,sdnalsi esoht fo eno no esuoh a dliub ew fi tahW
,taoc ytsud sih detsujda
”.od ot evah ll’tI“
”!koobelur eht ni ton s’ti tuB“
”,edistuo tfel eno eht saw ymereJ fI“ ”?saw tahW“
,no gnidnats erew yeht daorssorc eht erew gniht htfif dna htruof ehT
.giarC ta decnalg moT
.flah ni dedivid yltaen saw yks eht ,yltcerid tsomla
,tsrow eht gniraef detrats dah moT retfa dias eh ”,lleW“
”?ratiug eht htiw noteleks eht dna
,sdrac eht hguorht deppilf moT
,nees reve I dnah tsegnorts eht t’nia ti fi neve dna ,dab toN
?rewoT kraD eht ,hO“
”!sdaorssorc eht ta erif a‘ evah ot desoppus er’ew syas yletinifed ti tuB“
.snroht htiw tsirw eht ta dnuob
”.em htiw yalp ot nwod tas enoyna ecnis elihw elttil a n’erom neeb s’tI“
.euqapo ylraen dna trid htiw yerg erew nekorb t’nerew swodniw tahW
demraw dna ,sehcnuah sih no dettauqs eH
,moT dniheb gnidih yawflah ,detrulb giarC ”?uoy era ohW“
,sevarG fo gniK eht
emag eht fo tcejbo ehT“
.trap elbarapmocni eht t’nsaw ti tub
,moT derepsihw ”,enoyna ot gniklat
,elbat elttil eht fo edis htruof eht no gnittis saw enoemos
”.yrruh ralucitrap oN
,etoyoc a ro xof a eb ot llat oot saw eh taht dias evah dluow moT
,flesruoy fo ekas eht rof si yaw enO“
.kcab moor eht thguorb thgil rieht llit nees eb dluoc taht lla erew semalf eht niaga ,ssenkrad eht niaga
,on tub ,noil sselenam a dias evah dluow moT—tac gib A
,yrotS tsohG a si siht esuaceb
,ksed a saw ecalp sti ni dna
.snoitcurtsni evah ot meht detcepxe
.nooccar eht ot nialpxe ot stpmetta elituf s’mussop eht gnirongi
"?dneirf ,no tliub esuoh ruoy si senob ynam woH"
ton er’yehT“ .giarC derepsihw
.ereht ydobyna regnol on saw ereht taht dezilaer yeht erofeb
.nooccar eht ta nwod dekool dribgnikcom ehT
.denrut ksam eht ni nam ehT ”!yeH
”.emag siht ’niyalp detrats lla’y erofeb selur eht wenk uoy erus neeb evah ot thguo lla’y ebyaM“
leeh reh no denrut ehS
eciton yeht did neht ylno dna
”.uoy eb ot thguo tI
redluohs sih revo dellac eh
.yawa delevirhs sduolc eht dna
yawevird eht ssorca nwolb dah sevael daeD
,ytterp yrev saw tahT
.dnuorg eht dehcaer reve yeht erofeb tsim otni gnivlossid
esuaceB .spahrep ,dekcolb rO .enog
”,edistuo tfel tog eh sseug I“
,ti ksa ot htuom sih gninepo saw
.dnuos a ton edam yehT
,nrut ton did llits ehs ”uoy ot ton
,nehctik ruoy ni SDRAC EREW yeht nehw neve naem ot desoppus erew yeht tahw llet t’ndluoc I“
.kcilc llud naelc a htiw
,meht dniheb dniw eht
.pu ti dleh eh nehw dniw eht ni delttar
.emoh og I ylekil erom eht
,teerts eht nwod sevael daed wef a welb dniw ehT
.t’nac uoy syas selur eht ni gnihtyna s’ereht sa ees t’nod I sseuG
?pets rehtona ekat ew nehw hsinav annog tsuj ti t’nsI“ ”.suoires m’I
,mottob eht ta yltaen dedlof steehs ,ytpme
.dribgnikcom eht ecnivnoc ot desoppus wohemos saw flesmih meht gnidaer fi sa
!tiaW ?yalp ew od woH“
...“ .daeh sih koohs giarC ”…ll’I
”?ot thguo uoy erus uoY
”?ehs si ,uoy ot gniklat yllautca ton s’ehS“
.woleb sdleif eht ssorc swodahs eht dna ,selbbub ekil
,stekcop sih ni peed erew swap s’nooccar ehT
.noitom htooms gnol a ni
.gninniw yb niw t’nod uoy …oN“
.draob emag eht fo edis ,deipucconu
,denodnaba ton saw esuoh ehT
.epacsdnal eht saw gniht dnoces ehT
,yrots tsohg a eb ot tuo nrut t’nod taht yrots on
.neewollaH rof yllaicepse
.ti ni sdrow neeb dah ereht
.erofeb nees reve d’yeht gnihtyna ot elbarapmocni saw weiv eht
morf esnes sekam ekil leef uoy taht evif fo tes a ekam tsuJ“
,deppans mussop eht ”!selur eht ni sdnah gninniw eht fo snoitpircsed s’erehT“
?thgir ,sesol eno dna niw sreyalp eerht erehw trap a saw ereht rebmemer yletinifed I tub noitnetta hcum gniyap neeb evah ton thgim I“
”!taraccab ni dnah s’reknaB a
?sdrac si knuj modnar taht pu ekam tsuj ot dewolla yeht era yhW“
.dednamed giarC ”!?taht SAW tahW“
,detcejbo giarC ”,tiaW“
,dias nooccar eht
”.esaelp uoy yaw revehcihw ,yhW“
,yb evord yeht sa rac a morf
,enog dah ymereJ hcihw nwod eno eht morf daor etisoppo eht nwod denrut
,dethgil a otni nees d’yeht fi sa tlef tI
”.yresim ot sdael ti dna
”.efil ruoy lla fo esruoc eht enimreted lliw taht enO
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.drows reh werd ehS
seye emaceb selohbmuht neeb dah tahw dna ,ti gnidlofnu saw ymereJ neht tub
”!edud ,taraccab yalp ot woh wonk t’nod I“ .dias ymereJ
,gnirpS fo mitciV eht ,sthgiL fo eerhT eht ,egdelwonK
”!trap ykoops eht s’taht ,hO“
.dray edis eht ni ecnef knil niahc gniggas eht tsniaga delttar dna
,mih ot kaeps lliw I“ .giarC dias
,rewsna na dah giarC fI
.edisni teg ot yrruh a ni saw eh ekil mees ot tnaw t’ndid eh tub
”?ti sekat dna ni skaerb enoemos fi tahW“
”.pleh lliw taht selur eht ni gnihtemos eb ll’ereht“
.timov ot mih detcepxe flah moT dna gnivaeh saw tsehc siH
.enut ni ylerab ,lufnruom ,wols
,gnir yratenalp a saw ti dezilaer d’eh nehw
”!su fo htob rof sdrac hguone ton s’erehT“
”.ti yalp ot detnaw ohw eno eht er’uoy ,edud ,tihs a eb t’noD“
,dereens ehs ”,tnelis eb osla lliw uoY“ .nageb moT ”-emag eht naem uoy fi ,hU“
,esol od ew fi tuB“
,noisiv larehpirep sih ni tnemevom eht was eh nehw
.ti rof ecalp tseb eht ylbaborp s’taht neht ,si ti fi tahT“
,llew yrev mussop eht wonk t’ndid moT
.tnelis eb lliw uoy dna“
”,selur eht tog ev’I ,yrrow t’noD“
t’niA“ .sgnirts eht dehcuot ecno reven dah sdnah ynob eht taht
.dnah sih ni elppa na dah nooccar ehT ”?daorssorc eht“
tsrif eno ni selur eht deppirg ymereJ ”.taerG“
”.ti fo draeh reve d’ohw enoyna dnif t’ndluoc I
,gnorw dednuos rednuht ehT
”!kcab og uoy erus m’I tsael ta neht
deunitnoc reyalp ratiug lateleks ehT
fo tiurF ehT“ ”!won ton ,eduD“ .moT dias ”?tahw ,tiaW“
.sthguoht sih gnitalucitra ot emoc ot elba saw giarC tsesolc eht saw ”?tahw ,tiaW“
saw ksam draobdrac elttil eht fo noitcelfer eht
retsaf gnivom erew sduolc ehT
,giarC ta deralg moT ”,dlot saw I“
,mih pu werg snroht gniviL
,tfos eht dah sdrac ehT
.kciw eht no ,ylsuoenatnops
,flehskoob s’amdnarg fo pot eht no ees d’uoy dlo fo dnik eht dna ,deniatsretaw—
,pih reh no ton ,drows a dah ehS
.taht htiw gniog saw eh erehw erusnu saw giarC ”.si tI“ .dias moT
”.hguoht ,tuoba gniyrrow saw I tahw t’nsaw tahT“
,sthgil eht tuo nrut ,erif eht ritS
,seye s’moT otni peed dekool dna denrut giarC
,mih dniheb noziroh eht revo ekorb nus eht sepols eht ffo dellor eciov sih sA .gnicaneM
,sdnah fo riap a dah tI
,dednuos rednuht tnatsid dna
.emag eht pu tes ydaerla dah ymereJ
.deggurhs nam ehT
,wen saw esuoh eht ,til eno taht nehw dna
.ytpme saw moor ehT
”?su fo eerht ylno s’ereht fi dniheb tfel reyalp htruof a eb ereht nac woH
?loohcs hgih ni kcab ekil em dna uoy tsuj
.ertaehtihpma rebmit
.yzarc gnitca saw I diaS
.elbat eht fo sedis eerht dnuora tas yehT ”!haeY“
.ffulb rieht revo tpews sdnalsi yks eht fo eno fo wodahs hsiulb eht sa
.koobelur eht fo kcab eht hguorht ylsuoiruf deppilf ymereJ
.llits deyats reh fo tser eht tub ,dehsal liat reH
fo roloc eht erew nus eht fi teg d’uoy der fo dnik eht saw tI
”.’niyalp er’yeht yrots tahw llet nac dnah a syalp tahw ydobyreve ton sseug I
.teef rieht no selcanam erew erehT
”!rehtegot gniog er’eW
looc tnew meht dnuora ria ehT
,noitcesretni eht hguorht
a …ot esol thgim ew os“
.swodniw ytsud hgih eht dna
saw yas ot saw ereht gniht ylno eht taht dettimda eh erofeb
.dehcnuh erew sredluohs sih dna
.yltneconni ,deksa moT ”?sdnah ruo deyalp ew nehw dias uoy tahw tuoba klat annog ew ,oS...“  ].dne eht saw taht emussa ebyam renetsil eht tel ot hguone gnol ylerab tsuj ,ereh esuaP :ikahK ot ETON[  .yllufepoH .niaga daor taht klaw ot reven ,dnoyeb dna
saw sihT       DNE EHT
gnileef eht ekahs ot drah saw ti dna
.toos fo yltbus dellems taht ssenkrad ni dednepsus ,elbisiv saw taht lla saw emalf eht tnemom a roF
,ria thgin eht detarutas llits nikpmup derrahc-eldnac fo llems ehT .giarC dias
,dehgis moT ”,kniht I“
,kced eht ni si puC ytpmE ehT“
”?esle gnihtyna ’nidloh uoY .ruof s’tahT
.ti ni drac a dnif ot
.enog saw foor eht tub ,yltsom
kool ot gninnigeb erew yeht dnA
,thgit dnah s’giarC dleh moT ”.neht ,yaw ruoy nO“ ”.rehtegot
,sdrac torat driew ekil dekool yeht gniyas ot esolc emac eH
,derevocnu erew hcuoc dna riahc eht woN
,yuG ksaM eht taeb taht sdnah tog htob ev’ew llit gniog peek annog er’eW
.wons fo dleif a ni
,dias nam eht ”,yhW“
.niw annog er’eW“
.moor eht morf edorts dna
.etunim yna espalloc ot eud
”.evael dluoc I os sgniht gnirebmemersim eb tsum I dias I
.esuoh gninrub a fo foor eht no dehcrep lwo nA
,ta gnikool saw eh tahw rehtegot tup eh ecno
”?fo tuo hcnup knard I taht ssalg tohs citsalP“
.serutcip erew ereht daetsni tuB
”!koobelur eht ni neve ton s’tI
.hcum ees ot krad oot saw edisllih ehT
.loohcs hgih ni detad yeht wonk I“ .dias moT
”,wonk uoy ,tsuj ebyaM“
.noziroh eht ot yaw eht lla mih fo tnorf ni thgiarts retniop-resal tnew dna ,ytsud ,level
ti enod d’yeht emit eht yb dna sdnoces fo rettam a ni dehsinav dna ,detlem ,dellews
.lla ta enon saw ereht gnikniht rof nevigrof eb dluoc uoY
,eugnot sih no ’?emag siht teg uoy did erehw‘
”.uoy erofeb si wonk ton od uoy eciohc a si tI“
”.sediT fo ruoF ehT“
.t’nac uoy syas selur eht ni ’nihton t’niA“
”?tuoba taht saw tahW“
,sniatnuom sa egral sa emos ,sesuoh sa llams sa emos ,sknuhc ykcoR
saw tI“ ”?hguoht ,eldnac detnecs ezeerB naebirraC A“
.meht drawot nrut ton did ecaf reh
.redluohs sih no dnah a tup moT nehw evom t’ndid eH
?detsixe reveN ?tsoL ?daeD
,denedrah eciov s’moT ”,ton m’I“
.edistuo skcart eht fo eno ot tniop ot tpews drows reH
”!neves eht ro evlewt eht dedeen TSUJ I ,sgnir fo nevele dna ,net ,enin ,thgie eht dah I“
dnah sih tuo dleh moT
,deraeppa sduolC
”?sdrac hguone teg ton ot pu tes sdneirf ruoy tfel uoy retfa nevE
meht tsniaga gnikaerb erew sduolc eht taht hguone hgih erew emoS
.ereh reyarp ta saw nosrep eno ylnO
,dnuorg eht no detaes llits
.elbanigami gniht gniticxe tsom eht saw ti ekil ,dias ymereJ
”?thgir eman eht tog uoy erus uoY“
,kaeps lliw I rof ,netsil“
.sdnah ruoy ni pu dedne revetahw
,etihw lla gniraew
,stnaw ti erehw og ti tel uoy
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ro drocer a no ekil ,sevoorg ees dluoc yeht
,ecnelis tnatcepxe fo os ro tnemom a retfA ”.retal ro renoos
?daeh sti ,yrots yna ,yrots a evig uoy ,dneirf hO“
,niaga daor eht no erew yeht
,gniklat deppots ymereJ
.mih fo draeh reven …d’ehS
.klawedis eht no gnidnats saw giarC ”.eduD“
.won pleh dluow ti depoh dna ,sgnieB ,llew
.trap elbarapmocni eht t’nsaw llits taht tuB
skcart dna smroftalp ytpme eht ot srood ehT
.os gniyas ot tniop on saw ereht tub deerga moT
,derewsna eh ”,kniht I“
”?sdrac thgir eht era eseht erus uoy era“ ,moT dias ”,reJ“
.woleb tnemevom saw ereht esuaceB .pu
,sniur fo sniur erem erew elbisiv erew serutcurts wef tahW
cirbaf tneculsnart eht hguorht dewohs ylmid thgilerif ehT .denrut nam eht
,evom ton did drows eht tub
,doolb on werd yeht dna
.dias ksam eht ni nam ehT ”.dneirF eht fo dnaH
.tsrif olleh yas dluow meht fo hcihw gnirednow
.sdaorssorc eht hguorht welb dniw dloc A
”!edistuO tfeL naM htruoF dellac s’ti yhw s’tahT
,ytilibisiv otni kcab ylwols dedaf moor eht nehW
.yas ot gnihtyna dnif t’ndluoc giarC
.edisni yaw rieht edam dah hcihw fo emos
.dnuos tsethgils eht edam ti rehtehw noitacidni on llitS
,gniddew a gnidnetta enoemos ekil desserd saw eh dna
lardehtac krad a dah taht eno eht dewohs moT ”,lleW“ ”?yhw ,haeY“
”,dnoces yna su ot nrut annog s’eH“
,tnemom a doots eH
”?ereh deyats ew fi tahW“
.dnalsi yks a kcip“ ,giarC dias ”,no oG“
.wons debrutsidnu htaeneb gniyl fo retniw eritne na sekat taht
,kcab deknilb giarC dna moT
,nmutuA fo roivaS ehT“
.lla ta ksam eht htaenrednu
.noziroh eht no dekcol seye s’ymereJ ”!gnithgif oN
,UOY htiw gniog saw I fi tpecxe seitrap s’ecarG ot detivni tog reven I dna ,reh htiw pu ekorb uoy ecnis seitrap s’ecarG ot detivni teg t’nod uoY !eromyna tol gnikrap hcruhc eht ni tuo gnignah otni su kcirt ot ediryah a dna gnibbob elppa pu tes annog t’nsi puorG htuoY ehT“
.laer ecalp yna morf gnihtemos ekil dnuos t’ndid ti hguoht ,tnecca fo dnik emos gniod saw eH
”.puy ,tnargaV eht dna sdrowS fo egaS ehT“
.selur eht DAER dna daeha og lla’y ,thgir llA“
.eugra ot deraperp dna redluohs sih derauqs eh
”.sevlesruo pu ti tes t’nod ew fi thgin neewollah od ot GNIHTYNA evah annog ton er’eW
”!ereh sdnah gninniw eht ni ton s’tahT“
d’eh taht sessalg hguorht yllufelab meht ta dekool
.mih ot gniklat neeb t’ndah ymereJ hguoht ,delkcuhc nam eht ”?meht DAER“
.dewedlim saw roolf elit eht ,raja doots
”.ereht ,dneirf ruoy naht dnah retteb neve ,yob ,dab toN“
,neewteb ni tsuj si sihT
.yks eht otni yltneg esor
,pu gnikcip saw dniw eht ,rekciht dna
.dlrow dna efil s’regnarts a fo espmilg yratnemom a otni
”,edud ,em evael t’noD“ .dnah sih ekat giarC tlef moT
”!owt ward“ ro ”secaps eerht kcab og“ ro ”,stniop 5“ ekil sgnihT .ebyam ,seluR
?od ot gniyrt ew era sdnah tahW
”?sevlesruo pu ti gnittes‘
.yks nwad-erp yerg krad a tsniaga elbisiv ylerab erew sehcnarb enip fo sepahs ehT
.ezeerB naebbiraC ekil dellems erifpmac ehT
”,tlik yeht esoht dna
xob eht denepo ymereJ
.tem sdaor eht erehw renroc eht yb erifpmac eht ta sdnah sih
.dlofdnilb reh gnidulcni
”-dna ,ereh ekil kool neve ll’yeht tahw swonk ohw
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,tnerapsnart-imes
”!dne eht ta serocs erapmoc ew llit sdrac esoht ta kool ot steg ydobon dna
.depmuj htob yeht taht hguone tsaf rood eht denepo ymereJ
.stekcop trihstaews sih ni swap sih deffuts dna
.pets tsrif a koot eh sa
enohs dah ssalg deniats ecno erehw swodniw eht hguorht ezeerb looc ehT
”,siht sekam taht oS“ ”!dah I tahw
.kcab og uoy ,dnah a ekam uoY“
mih ot ylno elbisiv langis emos ta neht
.pu ti kool ot deirt I“
,erehwemos ti deppord t’ndah eh gniyarp
.sdaorssorc eht ta kcab sevlesmeht dnuof yehT
.enil til ylthgirb a tsuj ekil dekool ti tub
.eldnac tilnu dnoces a
”?ti t’nsi ,suoegrog si yllaer tI“
renroc eht ni loots a no tub
,sllaw eht no stops dedaf sseL
.giarC ot sdrac eht fo tser eht dessap ylkciuq moT ”?sih tuoba tahw
,taes sih koot mussop eht
”?yawyna taht od annog ew t’nereW“ .dias moT
meht fo htob ta gniknilb hsinif dluoc ymereJ erofeb ylitsah drawrof denael giarC ”!dnimreveN“
.ratiug pu taeb a gnidloh erugif a saw
.sselehtenon ,sgnileef drah erew erehT .enog saw eh dnA
sraw sselesu ni tlik sreidlos
.gnihton saw ereht dna ,tuo welb seldnac eerht lla tnemom a retfA
sdnah sih gnidnib ,mih dnuora dnuow
”,s’eh kniht uoy oS“
telhpmap ysmilf ehT
,riahc gnidlof ynit fo dnik emos saw ti taht saw
,murd latem tnaig a edisni gniohce saw ti ekil
”.og ew sa nialpxe nac I“
"?fo draeh neve reven uoy seman esohw taht erofeb elpoep fo sraey fo sderdnuh ynam woh
”?eldnac a yficeps selur ehT“
,rehtegot esnes edam taht seno eht uoy evig ot deirt I“
?elppa siht tog ev’I“
loot nettogrof a srenroc emos nI
”.hguoht woh onnud I
:esle erehwemos neeb d’yeht niaga nwod ti gnittup dna toof sih pu gnikcip neewteb tub
”.gnineppah saw tahw wenk I hsiw tsuj I
,ylizal dehcterts ,teef sih ot tog nam ehT
”?mih ot deneppah tahw …oS“
,htruof eht no ecaf draobdrac elttil eht tes eh neht dna
.edisllih eht no erehwyreve erew yehT
,draob eht fo smra eht fo eno gnola regnif a nar ymereJ
!wons eht ni erutcetihcra cihtog emos saw ti“
.taht mih dlot d’ohw ksa dna
,teerts eht nwod dedaeh dna denrut yehT
,der si tesnus a yaw eht der t’nsaw tI
,trid saw tI .daor eht saw
elbat edisdeb a no ti ediseb dna
”?lla ta dnuora ksa uoy diD“
.me‘ nwo uoy ekil selur eht tuoba klat uoY“
.ylraelC .sraey ni ereht devil dah ydoboN
”.flesruoy rof ees ll’uoy
.htaerb sih hctac ot thguof moT
,daeh sih revo ,cra htooms a ni sdrac evif daerps eH
tsehc sih ta yltcerid detniop saw pit drows eht hguoht tub ,desiar sdnah
.niw nac taht sdnah fo tsil a t’nia tahT“
,niaga deraeppa giarC dna moT nehW
ti gnissorc revir a htiw ,nialp decarret a daerps meht woleB
,llew yrev mih wenk giarC fi erus neve t’nsaw
,nam eht ton ,meht dnuora erehwyreve morf emac ti tub ,lworg a saw ereht
.gnisol ton yb niw uoY
evah d’eH .sah ti sa gnol sa tsal ot tnaem ton repap fo leef yredwop ,htooms
.daorssorc eht fo retnec eht ot deppets
hguor a yb dednuorrus egats yssarg a fo tnorf eht ot edorts—
.rehtegot gnikcits er’eW .erac t’noD“
,oot drac a sekat naM htruoF eht nrut yrevE“
.ria eht ni gnuh yeht dna
”.syas emag eht fo eman eht ekiL“
”?ereht ni llits si emag eht knihT“ ”.wonk t’nod I“
.llits tsomla saw dniw ehT   .floWcaM boR yb
.nooccar eht drawot klawedis eht nwod gniklaw dribgnikcom eht tsap dna
”.evol I ohw eno fo dnah eht dna“
.meht gnihctaw ,yawa secap wef a gnidnats nam eht dna
.ekam ot eciohc a evah ,sueddahT fo nos ,samohT ,uoY
s’tahW .raf os ,no gnorts neeb uoy nihtemos t’nia selur eht ’niwonk esop’s I tub
noitseuq eht dah moT
thgin ta moor deniatrucnu
.dessap wodahs ehT
ekil ti fo knihT“
”.emoh uoy gnitteg m’I neht dna
,yks eht hguorht yltneg tfird sniatnuom eht dehctaw yehT ”.haey ,taht ebyaM“
?nwot erehwon siht ni seitrap SEOD neve esle lleh eht ohw dna
.dnah reh ni dehtaehs tsuj
.egarim taeh ni gniremmihs
,rehtona fo ekas eht rof si rehto ehT“
,drazil a saw ehS
,kconk ot detpmet saw dribgnikcom eht dna
”!deirt t’nevah uoY
,daeh sih koohs ksam eht ni nam ehT
.draobdrac fo elip delgna ylegnarts a tuo dellup dna—
”.siht fo tuo teg ew woh dna skrow siht woh wonk uoy em llet ot uoy deen I“
,lliswodniw eht no eldnac elgnis a saw
”.si eh revetahw rof drow a s’ereht fi onnud I ?edistuO
.meht dniheb saw wodniw neercs eht hguorht tresed dekabnus eht dna
.si ti revetahW .ecalP
,yalp RUOY s’taht ,thgirlA“
,retnuoc eht dniheb ro sevlehs eht no gnihton saw erehT
,tesnuS ,namahS eht
.edisni mih dewollof yehT
”,hguone tuoba dah I“
teiuq saw ksam eht dniheb eciov ehT
”!ereh selur eht tog ev’I“
”!ENO !EROM ENO tsuJ“
.giarC dias ”.tihs hO“
GNIHTON yalp I fI“
,ffurdnad ekil selgnihs gniddehs
ecaf a saw ereht taht eveileb flesmih ekam ot drah saw tI .esle gnihton
”?ereht si esle ohW“
spets tnorf eht gnibmilc
”!thgin neewollah gnihtemos GNIOD yllautca dna tuo gniog otni debirb teg ot evah t’ndid I tsael ta“
.dniheb uoy gnivael“
.deredluom xob draobdrac dedracsid ro
snwap eerht eht koot nooccar ehT .dias giarC ”,eniF“
koobtxet ecneics dlo na morf noitartsulli na ekil ,hteet erbas dah eh
”!skrow emag eht woh ton s’tahT
.noonretfa etal ,neewollah retfa yad eht saw tI
,eldnac eht ot txen ,ecaps retnec eht no meht deppolp dna
,niaga drows eht dehtaehs ehs
.rab a neeb evah thgim
.gnihtyreve tnereffid ,ria tnereffid ,yks tnereffid
”.ereh ’niteem er’ew yhw s’tahT
.ynam gnoma esuoh elbakramernu eno fo
!trats ot ydaer m’I“
.dias ksam eht ni nam ehT
.yks eritne eht dessorc d’yeht
,yrteop ,seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.detuohs ymereJ ”!no gnah tiaW“
,purys hguoc yrrehc
.ksam knalb a saw nees eb dluoc taht lla tub
,tekcop sih ni gud moT ”…siht dnA“
”edistuO tfeL naM htruoF“   :yojne esaelP
,yletilop ,dedualppa giarC dna moT
,ylpeed gnihtaerb ,sselnoitom
,elpoep fo sretsulc elttil eht ees ot nageb gairC dna moT detsujda seye rieht sA
,kcab snoitcerid rof ksa ll’I“
.dias yllanif moT
,sthgil samtsirhc pu gnittup
,efil ot derettups emalf A
,diarfa dna delffab ,mih ediseb deraeppa tsuj d’ohw elpoep owt eht diap eh naht dnim erom on meht yap ot demees eh dna
emit gnol a rof teerts eht nwod dna pu dekool moT
,noitcelfer eht ni
.wodniw eht ot kcab sih
,ksam sih fo—cirbaf saw ti fi—
,drows eht htiw ydal siht ...dnA“
.erew ylbamuserp spil sih erehw fo tnorf ni regnif eno dial nam ehT
,sllaw eht no elpoep gnilims fo serutcip
ecafrus neerg nialp eht no serutcip gnitnirp rehtob dluow yeht erofeb morf
.pets txen eht ekat ot
.ffulb ykcor a fo pot eht ta doots yehT
”,ti tog eh erehw wonk t’nod I“
.shtolc ygnid htiw derevoc
.tnuocca trofwolliP sih no sekoj dab dna
,nepo eht ni gnidnats sehcra
.thgin suoiverp eht tneps d’yeht erehw teerts eht ssorca esuoh eht morf evom t’ndid seye siH
taht nwonk evah ot desoppus erew yeht taht htob dias enot sih tub
.detnioppasid ,evisired
.pets a koot moT nehT
drawrof denael yeht litnu ylraelc nees eb t’ndluoc yehT
,gnihtees saw ymereJ
ylesolc erom dekool yeht fI
,rethgit tekcaj sih dellup moT
thguoht tsrif s’moT
:ytpme regnol on saw ti
.ot tnaem d’eh fi sa kool t’ndid ti dna
,teef sih ot nooccar eht dellup dna
.dneirf dlo na rof gnikool saw I diaS“ .deggurhs giarC
.ereh neeb dah erutinruf ro serutcip taht sngis ylno eht erew ,teprac eht no stops delpmart ssel
sevael nwolbdniw yb ylno detnuah saw hcihw
,niar emoceb dah wons eht
.serifpmac fo sniamer dloc eht dnuora slwoc dna sepac ni deldduh
,gnignir erew meht htaeneb dnuorg eht fi sa ,lleb eguh a ekil dnuos a emac ereht nehw
”,srobhgien eht ot deklat I“ .dias moT
,niaga evisneffo eht no mih tup dluow taht gnihtemos rof gnihcraes
semag driew sih fo eno gniyalp dna esuoh s’ymereJ ot gniog si woH“
”.ti fo tuo setib elpuoc a koot I“ .derepsihw eh
?sdrac doog eht era hcihw llet ew od woh dnA“
,daor eht no neeb d’yehT
.tsiaw eht ot deppirts ,seenk sih no ,gnuoy ,retto nA
”.meht esu ot woh llet t’nac I“
,yruf deniatnoc ylerab htiw ymereJ ot denrut giarC ”,reJ“
,ratla eht fo tfel saw tahw no dial romra neerg-gnirps dna drows trohS
,sllaw eht tsap ,meht tsap dekool dna
,emag a rof gnihtemos ton
”,efac eht ta ,annaeT ot deklat I“
,hsurbtniap kciht a yb tfel
,hguoht ,sdnah eerht rehtegot tup ot daor eht no sdrac hguone ylno s’erehT
,dnuos a edam evah dluohs ti ekil dekool tI
”.now evah taht sdnah fo tsil a s’tahT
”!edud ,rehtie emag taht yalp ot woh wonk t’nod I“ .dias ymereJ
.saw ti noitcerid hcihw llet ot elbissopmi
dnah eerf sih desiar moT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
stekcos eye ytpme desiar yehT ”.gniticer
,ksam eht dniheb ,elbisivni saw noisserpxe s’nam ehT
”!ot tnaw I sa hcum sa flah toN“
,emos morf deliart seniV
.yks eht saw gniht driht ehT
”,ti yalp ot gniog yeht era woH“ .dias giarC
”?su ot gniklat eh sI“
”.dniheb uoy gnivael ton m’I“
.ksa ot ecnahc a tog reven moT noitseuq rehtona saw ’?TAHT si kcuf eht ohw‘ os
.esol ew nehw sneppah revetahw ro sevals nilbog otni denrut gnitteg dna ,ecaf-a-evah-t’nseoDcM ypeerC htiw emag diputs s’ymereJ gniyalp dna kcab gniog fo daetsnI“ ”?tahW“
.mih bmilc ot gniyrt ti tlef d’eh sa
”?neht ,’nisoohc eb sallef uoy ahcae ll’daor hcihw dnA“
.sgnir eht ot lellarap wobniar a detniap sllafretaw eht fo eno hguorht meht dniheb thgilnus ehT
.tuoba gniklat er’uoy tahw dnatsrednu t’nod …I“
dniw eht ni detfihs hcnarb daed A
,enog saw deb latipsoh eht
,dribgnikcom eht ta dekool ksam eht ni nam ehT
”edistuO tfeL naM htruoF“
.denodnaba saw ,raf os nees d’yeht ecalp yreve ekil
,noitisop citamard ssel fi elbanosaer erom a otni kcab sessalg sih gnihsup ,dias ymereJ ”,uoy erussa I ,hO“ .dias moT
”?cigam“ ,denworf moT
.erofeb ti draeh reve dah giarC naht redrah saw eciov s’dribgnikcom ehT ”.oN“
”!dniheb uoy gnivael ton m’I“
.nekcirts dekool ymereJ
.yawyna ,thginot toN
.hcruhc llams eht fo tfel elttil saw erehT  .pets a koot dna
.tiaw ot evah dluow ti
.ebircsed eugolonom roiretni sih tel ot ton
”!meht daer llits nac eW“
eno dna desufnoc owt no thgileldnaC
.t’ndid yeht desirprus t’nsaw eh taht dna
.wodahs mid fo htaws daorb a saw meht woleb senalp eht ssorca dna
”?edistuo tfel ...T’NSAW
,elbakramernu ynam gnoma esuoh elbakramer eno eht morf yawa
.rehto eht ni ti otni ruop ot tuoba saw eh akdov paehc fo tohs eht
,dias ymereJ ”,ko s’tI“
dna“ ,tar a ebyam ro ,desseug evah dluow moT ,ecno ,tibbar a—
,dah yeht xis eht morf sdrac dekculp moT
”?elppa taht tog llits ev’uoy
.raeh ot tnasaelp neeb evah dluow taht eno ton dna
,detcelfer ecaf tnarebuxe yllacitsabmob
,ereht ,tsrif dnah sih swohs taht sdaorssorc eht ot kcab lla su sllac ohw eno eht s’ti yllausu“
”?sdnalsi gnitaolf eseht“
,sdeew fo elgnat a saw dray ehT
”?neht ,drac tsal ruoy
dribgnikcom dna nooccar eht dnuof ti llit teerts nabrubus krad eht nwod noitcesretni eht morf
,seye tsenoh htiw ,esolc kooL ?worg ti tel uoy
,elbat nehctik eht no ssorc draobdrac depraw yltneg eht ta derutseg giarC
”.yats NAC ew kniht t’nod I
.snoitadnuof enots erab fo serauqs
.sdaor eht fo eno nwod denrut dna
,trohs deppots dribgnikcom ehT
”?ecaf ot erad reven nem tsom sa hcus egnellahc a rof deraperp uoy erA“
”!sevlesruo rof tuo kool ot tog ev’eW !yltcaxE“
,ratiug a saw dnuos ylno ehT
.dnuorgrednu saw ti ekil tlef gnidliub eht tuoba gnihtemoS
,srehto morf dedacsac sllafretaw
taes sih ot deppolf dah gairC
,deraeppasid dlrow eht neht dnA
.krow t’nod emag siht woh em ’nillet klof fo“ ,ksam eht ni nam eht dias
,sdaeh rieht evobA
,noitats niart ehT
.yks lufniap eht rednu
,meht degnarraer ,kcab eno tup
.moT derepsihw ”,os kniht t’nod I“ .giarC derepsihw
”,ekil gnihtemos od dluoc I snaem taht oS“
.drawkcab nekops tsuj dah moT ekil
.esab eht ot tsomla denrub ,tilnu
.emag eht sesol tfel nosrep tsal eht os
”yllacificeps ,eldnac a toN“
.kaeps t’ndid llits eH
.ffo deliart giarC
.noitanigami sih ylno saw htaenrednu lluks eninac a fo eniltuo feirb eht taht flesmih dlot moT dna
.dehsinav sdaorssorc ehT
,dnah eno ni hcnup fo puc a ,denworf moT
!nwod yal ot dnah a tog neve s’esle enoyna rehtehw nees neve tnia uoy dna ydaerla ’nipirg dna ’niugra er’uoY“ .detcejbo ymereJ
.tsrif snialp eht dna daor eht ta kool uoy ekam dluow taht yks fo dnik eht saw tI
,ylknalb ,kcab dekool giarC
,htaed otnu yraew sevals dna srekrow ,yrgnuh deid sa klof rooP"
.flow a eb ot llat oot osla saw eh tub
”?sdnah eseht ekam ew od woH“
,yhtaerb dna peed eciov ,dias eh ”,neht lleW“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”?snoitanibmoc eht era tahW
,dias moT ”,gniyas tsuj m’I“
”,gnivom er’yeht kniht I“
.raeppasid ot nigeb dna ,tsiwt ,evom
.mra gnol ylgnivrennu eno desiar eH
.esle erehwyreve dna
.gnissim dna ffo nekorb saw
.erofeb deticxe siht mih nees reven d’eh tub
.dlrow sihT .ereh ,hu
,snretnal'o kcaj yawa gniworht elpoep tsap
,lluf saw moor eht
,htaenrednu elzzum eht fo epahs eht ,pot pu sraE
,renilcer a dna hcuoc a saw ereht
.daeha steg ymereJ .daeha steg gnihT ksaM eht ,tser ew fI“ .deksa moT
,doots llits sehcra dna srallip ehT
”.taht ekil ’nitadamocca m’I
.em llet uoY“ ”?taht s’tahW
,thgin tsal ffo dehctiws dah ymereJ taht ,thgilhcrop eht dna
.puC ytpmE taht tog uoy yned t’nac I dna
tresed der thgirb tub edistuo gnihton saw erehT
,rotcudnoc artsehcro na ekil doots eH
”?ksam arepo imagiro
”.daorssorC eht ta naM htruoF dellac saw tI“
devom ylerab eh tub
”.sdrac xis tog ylno ev’ew dna“ ,decniw giarC
,smossolb dna sdub htiw daeh sih gninworc dna
!mih fo eno ,su fo eerhT
.yrt ot noitanilcni on tlef eh taht doog saw ti os htuom sih morf gniruop snoitseuq suoiruf eht deppots evah t’ndluoc moT
,dias daetsni dna dnim sih degnahc neht
.derepsihw nooccar eht
”?og I od yaw hcihW
,desserpminu dna drah saw eciov reh ”,uoY“
.sdnah rieht ni saw tahw deyalp yehT
.moT ot dias giarC
”.ti gniyalp tuoba saedi yna teg annog s’ydobon erehW
,ecaf s’moT ni selur eht gnivaw
”.daorssorC eht ta naM htruoF‘ dellac saw ti em dlot ohw eno eht era UOY“
”!giarC ,eromyna loohcs hgih ni ton er’eW“
niaga gnihsinav erofeb
.ni-devilnu saw ti tub
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,elbisiv saw ecaf sih fi mih yfitnedi ot elba neeb evah dluow ebyam eH
.onnud I“ ”?daed“
tsurc ekilrepap ytrid fo tros eht otni desuf dna
,daed deppots ratiug eht fo dnuos ehT
senobkeehc emaceb sbat neeb dah tahw dna
,drawrof deppets giarC ”,yakO“
.ssarg wen fo llems eht deirrac
.gnillaf saw wons wodniw eht hguorhT
.drah dewollaws eH
.ligiv sih ot mih gnivael dna
.sdaor eht gnola ward uoy sdrac eht morf dnah gninniw a rehtegot tup ot si
”.tnaw uoy fi ,egdelwonK fo tiurF eht ti ’nillac ees dluoc I
.elcsum fo niatnuom a saw eh htaenrednu tub