,sehsid eht gnihsaw ,loohcs rof gniyduts
”!ereh ydaerla er’yeht ,tihs hO“
”?uoy era ,won naiiawaH redro ot gniog t’nera uoY“
,gnorts a ffo evag lasuora s’lakcaj ehT
.huh hU“ .taht noitnem ot xelA rof emit eht t’nsaw won tub ,oot yxes dna ”,…etamesuoh ym
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.dekrims xof ehT ”.od I tub ,hO“
,tohs dah xelA ,emit on ni dna did eh sa xof eht revo gninael
.desolc flah seye
.denediw nirg ehT
,oeL dias ”,em s’taht ,haeY“
.moorhtab eht drawot deklaw eh sa dehgual xof ehT ”.tuls azzip uoY“
,xof eht fo eerf flesmih deggut oeL sa xelA depley
.ruf sih gnittam ebul htiw kcils wap ehT
”.taht wonk ot desoppus t’nera uoY“
.xelA ot revo gnipeerc
,tfahs eht htiw emit sih koot eH
,repeed ni flesmih dehsup oeL ,xelA rednu flesmih tog eh ecnO
,ti denepo lakcaj eht nehW
”.neht uoy rof laiceps gnihtemos od ot evah ll’I“
.enohp sih tuo dellup dna
.em ot taem fo eceip a tsuj naht erom yaw era uoy ,yeH“ .deyalps srae siH ”?uoy ot taem fo eceip a tsuj ,I ma tahW“
spih sih deppirg dna
ti fi ,noitanigami evitcarevo na gnivah htiw gnorw gnihton si ereht ,yeH“
.xof eht drawot drawrof hctorc sih gnisserp
:tihs diputs tuoba maerd tsuj I“
,tuhs seye sih dewercs xelA
”,thgit er’uoy ,doG“
.thgieh tsiaw tuoba morf lakcaj eht ta pu kool dluoc eh os elttil a riahc eht pu tperc xof ehT
.elbat eeffoc eht no azzip eht gnittup ,hcuoc eht ot revo kcab emac dna ,rood tnemtrapa eht dekcol dna desolc oeL ”.oot uoY“ ”.thgin
si yrots s’yadoT   si yrots s’yadot dna
”.ekorb erew uoy dias uoy thguoht I“
.em rof evitaerc steg dnim ym ti fi ti pleh t’nac I“
.spih sih detfihs lakcaj ehT
roolf eht otno hcuoc eht ffo dellor xelA
”.daeh ruoy revo sdnaH“
dna kcen sih fo og tel lakcaj ehT
.ados fo nac a gnihctulc
”.enadnum ytterp eb ot sdnet tI
,taem gnitteg eb ot gniog saw eh wenk xelA ,azzip sih no egasuas dna inoreppep detnaw eh dias eh nehW
.siht gnihctaw daeh sih koohs tsuj lakcaj ehT
”.redrah elttil a knihT“
deffuh lakcaj ehT
.mih ot kcab emac mih fo edisni peed gnieb oeL fo egami ehT
dluow I“ .taht wonk ot deen t’ndid lakcaj eht tub
,tsniaga elggurts ot gnihtemos mih evig dluow tI
.esnopser sih rof detiaw lakcaj eht sa hself sih tsniaga ezarg gnaf a tlef xof ehT
”,hguoht doog dnuos yllaer seod azziP“ .deredduhs oeL
,drah kcor ydaerla saw kcoc s’xof ehT
.emit eht lla taht em llet uoY .haey ,haeY“
ylisae pmur s’xof eht otni pit eht deppils oeL os ,ydaer dna deticxe ydaerla saw xelA
”,taht ta kool ,huh ,hO“
.dnuora tfihs mih fo edisni tfahs eht gnileef
”.thginot egasuas detnaw I“
,setunim ytriht ot ytnewt ni ereh eb dluohs tI“
.egasuas emos gnikcil tsuj htiw yawa teg thgim eh thginot thguoht eh tub ,erofeb onroiGiD rof kcid a nekat t’ndah eh ekil t’nsaw tI
”?egasuas fo eceip a yb dekcuf gnieb tuoba demaerd uoY“
.ecnartne raer sih tsniaga pu flesmih gnisserp oeL tlef eh sa demriuqs dna tnemeticxe ni depsag xelA
,delffum ,oeL derepsihw
”.ekorb ton m’I sseug I“
”,setunim ytriht ekat eb ot gniog erew yeht dias uoy thguoht I“ .lakcaj eht dessih
”,tekcap rovalf elohw eht dda t’nod ,oS“
,lakcaj eht dias ”,yawa skcolb wef a ylno er’yehT“
.ylitsul delworg eh
.sdoog eht gnisuba oN !yeH“
.yawa gninrut saw xof eht sa lakcaj eht dias ”?xelA yeH“
”.nuf erom ti sekam tI
.mih kcuf dluoc eh os sgel detfil ydaerla s’xof eht kcab gnisserp
.krow ta kcuts gnieb dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”!haeY“ .mih gnillif
”.peels ruoy ni dial uoy steg
.ylwols deggaw liat siH
.gnorts saw tnemtrapa eht fo tuo gnimoc tnecs ehT .yawa gnikcab
,kool desirprus a mih evag lakcaj eht
”azziP rof gnixoF“
”.azzip no elppaenip ekil t’nod I wonk uoY .no emoc hO“ ”.naiiawaH ebyaM“
,taert sih nrae ot detnaw eH
,pot no kcab gnibmilc erofeb xof eht deregnif ylkciuq eH
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.yawecnartne eht morf moor gnivil eht fo trap taht ees t’ndluoc uoy ecnis saw eh erehw deyats yllacigetarts xelA
.xof eht otni rebmem deit sih gnidnirg
,hcuoc eht no saw eH
?yako maerd a saw ti ,yeh dna“
.lakcaj eht ot pu ti gnissot dna sdnah sih morf ti gnieerf xof eht dias ”,trihs ym esU“ ”.tihS“
”,rehtegot inoreppep dna egasuas teg did uoy naem I“
,riahc ni kcab denael lakcaj ehT
”.tae dluoc I“ .delims neht dna
ruf sih edam tahw tuo dnuof ydaerla dah lakcaj ehT .taht dekil eh dna
,xelA delbmum ”?ahW“
”.uoy ot ti evig ot gniog m’I dna thginot egasuas detnaw uoy dias uoy lleW“
erutseg gninoitseuq a ni edis ot nwod deppord eno neht dna pu tnew rae siH
,dneirf ym er’uoY
delkcuhc xof ehT
”.laed a ekam nac ew spahreP“
.ni gnitsurht dna spih s’xelA gnibbarg ,dias eh
.deggurhs lakcaj ehT
.xof eht edisni muc yllanif ot oeL gnisuac
”,wonk t’nod srobhgien eht ekil ,esaelp hO“
.tniop eht t’nsaw taht tub
.pmur s’xof eht revo emos gnilzzird yb pu xof eht debul dna flesmih no tnuoma doog a deruop eH
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
”,decnivnoc eb nac I“
.enohp sih deppat oeL
.setamefil ton ,setamesuoh
.lakcaj dekcab-kcalb eht detnurg
.deggurhs xof ehT
”!em liops od uoY
.deffuh lakcaj ehT
”,egasuas ruoy saw ti tub ,sey naem I !oN“
,detnap eh ”,esaelp seY“
meht fo tuo tfahs sih gut ot gnivah ,srexob sih ffo deppils eH
”.em llet uoy t’nod yhW“
,eerf sdnah sih deppils evah dluoc xelA ,detnaw eh fI
.niaga ni demmals eh sa worg ecnatsiser eht gnikam tonk gnillews sih ,oeL deffuh
,trihs eht ffo llup ot detrats eH
pley dna pmuj ot xof eht gnisuac pmur s’xelA dekcams eH
,enohp sih no gnippat ,dias eh
,seye sih desolc dna kcab srae sih dekcilf xof ehT
.enohp sih no ecalp lacol a pu gnillup ,dedda eh
.srae sih fo eno otni repsihw dna xof eht ot esolc elzzum sih gnirb dluoc eh os ,thgiew sih detfihs dna xof eht ot deit llits
”.thginot niaga nemar eb lliw ti sseug I
,esnet dna reviuq xelA edam sihT
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
”?ew did ,tsurc deffuts redro t’ndid eW“
”.uoy htiw egasuas ym erahs ot em rof yppah etiuq erew uoy llacer ot mees I
,drawrof denael lakcaj ehT
.yojne I taem emos rof gnihtyna od d’I dna ,yrgnuh m’I ,lleW“
.detnap eh ,desolc seyE
.moc.gnirpsyad-
.erac ot tnemom eht ni pu thguac
.elzzum s’xof eht fo edisrednu eht elkcit ot nwod dehcaer lakcaj ehT
deggurhs tsuj oeL
.tuo dna ni flesmih dekrow lakcaj eht sa denaom xelA
”?ti no egasuas htiw gnihtemos redro ot uoy rof ekat ti dluow tahW“
.strohs s’lakcaj eht fo reppiz eht ta deggut yltneg dna pu dehcaer wap A
.ekauqhtrae na ekil gnikahs ydob elohw sih tlef eh ylnedduS
.dnuos gniggag a edam lakcaj ehT
.thgin doog a evaH“
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
.riahc eht tsniaga depmuht liat sih dna
strohs s’lakcaj eht fo nottub eht didnu xof ehT
sffucdnah tfihsekam sa stsirw sih dnuora depparw ti gnivael ,mih deppots oeL tub
,hcuoc eht ot txen riahc eht ni nwod deppolp lakcaj ehT
?selbategev htiw rehtegot inoreppep dna
.taorht s’xelA dnuora elzzum
.dne eht ta pu delruc dna elzzum sih tuo dellor eugnot s’xelA
,htaehs sih delzzun xof eht sa
”.tuoba gnimaerd saw I azzip tsuj t’nsaw ti os yakO“
”.pu em nesool dna neht netfo erom siht od dluohs eW“
.lakcaj eht fo gnihtaerb deggar ylgnisaercni eht ot gninetsil ,thgiew sih detfihs siH
.gel sih rednu dennip saw ti tub ,pu ti revoc ot liat sih kcilf ot deirt eH
.egarevel emos dnif ot detrats eh sa
.htaehs dna tfahs sih revo pu meht gniggard dna strohs sih gnibbarg
”.ytsan si ffuts paehc taht kniht I wonk uoY“
,gnikorts nageb oeL ,niaga tfahs enipluv eht dnuora desolc wap s’lakcaj eht sa dna
”?taht od I dluow yhw ,oeL“
,roolf eht no kcab tas xelA erofeb
.azzip rof demottob I oS“
.noitnetta lluf ot gnimoc saw tfahs sih sa hcuoc eht no enohp eht dessot dna azzip eht no redro dekcilc xelA ,yllaniF
.reprahs ,regnorts saw ti
.mih fo edisni llits tonk eht gnileef ,spih sih delggiw eH
.htaehs s’lakcaj eht fo tuo gnikeep pit knip eht dessik dna
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
elbat dne eht no nwod knird sih tup oeL
.oeL teg dluoc eh pu dekrow woh ees ot tub
”.tuo dnif ll’uoy dna kcab eiL“
”.netfo erom uoy htiw enim erahs dluohs I“
”?thgin eht rof ni nrut ot ydaer uoy era ro rennid emos teg ot tnaw uoy ,yeH
.trihs-t rehto eht no dellup dna ,edisa ti gniworht ,trihs ykcits eht ffo dellup oeL ylkciuQ
.erac t’ndluow yug azzip eht tub ,mih no thgit elttil a saw tI
.gnilims dna elttil a kcab gninael ,oeL dias
.pu dekrow ydaerla saw eh dna hcum oot elttil a lakcaj roop eht desaet d’eH
tnemom a rof deredisnoc xof ehT
,gur eht no stops tog yeht fI
.delims xof ehT ”?gnihtynA“
”.gnihtemos ro eseehc htiw dellif gnieb tuoba gnihtemos ,thgir hO
xes gnirud tub ,tnemtrapa eht ni tneserp syawla saw tnecs eht ,oeL htiw ni devom d’eh ecniS .ksum railimaf
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.delkcuhc lakcaj ehT
.meht rednu gniggaw liat ,dias eh
.spih s’xof eht deppirg dna
.eugnot sih no ti fo gnileef eht gnirovas ,ylwols rebmem eht pu gnikcil
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tfahs sih tuo gniward
.saedi tnereffid dah ,hguoht oeL
”.lla ta gnihtoN .hU“
”?yxof ,detnaw uoy tahw siht sI“
.denaom eH ”.ris seY“ ”.reduoL“
”.yawyna ylrae llits s’tI“
,azzip naht erom tol a fo gnimaerd neeb d’eh ,yakO
,tew dna ecin ti teg ot erus gnikam
dne eht ni dehsats ebul fo elttob eht dehsif oeL
?tahW“ .gniggaw liat
er’eW“ .enohp sih pu gnikcip lakcaj eht dias ”,ton ebyam ,haeY“
.gnar ylneddus llebrood eht tub ,esle gnihtemos yas ot gniog saw eH .deggurhs oeL
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ylkciuq dekorts lakcaj ehT
.mih revo gnidnats lakcaj eht ta gniknilb
,drawrof gninael dias eh ”?yllaer hO“
.staem eht lla redro uoy nehw od ll’I tahw ees uoy llit tiaW“
”,uoy tel I fi yad lla taht htiw yalp ll’uoY“
.xelA no gnisucof srae
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.wap eno ni dehctulc llits rellortnoc emag oediv eht
.trihs s’xof eht pu deggut eH
.dezeeuqs saw tonk sih sa
.llews ot detrats dah tonk s’oeL ”.ris …seY“
”.thgir lla ti nrae ll’uoy ,hO“
.moorhtab eht ot klaw dluoc eh os flesmih dnuora thgit liat sih delruc eh os ,gnihtyna no pird ot tnaw t’ndid eH
.taem ruoy lla em eviG“ .xof eht deppiy
,esruoc fo nosaer ,nihtiW“
.ti no llits muc deird htiw trihs sih ta decnalg eh dna niaga gnar llebrood ehT
gnirpsyaD seyEthgiN yb
.liat sih no gnittis pots dluoc eh os dnuora detfihs xelA
seyethgin//:sptth ,etisbew sih tuo kcehc ro
.rehtegot meht gniyt tonk eht
hcuot eht ta derevihs dna ylduol denaom xof ehT .oeL detnap
.teprac eht no niats ebul a saw ereht was eh ,nwod gnicnalG
,taorht sih ta deppin etib yalp rednet a dna ,kcen sih revo dehsaw htaerb toH .hsulf
.sruof lla no riahc eht ot revo delwarc dna
”.ssendoog yseehc ruoy htiw em lliF
”.seisatnaf evah ot doog s’tI
eeffochtiwflow@ ta
.emit tsal denialpmoc uoy ekiL“
.ria eht ni xes fo tnecs eht gnihctac ,eson reh delknirw dna ecnaraeppa delevehsid sih ni koot ehS
oot saw eh tub ,lewot a teg ylbaborp dluohs eH
”…em ni egasuaS“ ”.huh
,eeffoc rof tnahcnep a htiw flow A
.dekrims lakcaj ehT
”?egasuas tnaw uoy ,oS“
.eson sih htiw hctorc s’lakcaj eht dnuora deffins dna revo denael eH
”.tfel azzip nezorf yna evah t’nod ew tub ,azziP“
.oeL dias ”,peelsa era uoy nehw tihs pu dekcuf emos elbmum uoy ,naM“
egasuaS“ ”.skrow eht em wohs uoy t’nod yhw ,skrow eht deredro I ecnis dna
.dnuorg eht no meht gnidracsid ,raewrednu dna strohs sih ffo dellup dna
,rebmem nwo s’xelA htiw gniyalp detrats eh erofeb xof eht otni nwod yaw eht lla ti gnitteg
”.niaga smaerd ruoy fo eno ekil skool tahT“
?pu uoy ekow I erofeb tuoba gnilbmum erew uoy taht saw tahW .huh hU“
,tnemom a rof deredisnoc eH
,sruof lla no nwod tog neht ,tuo reward elbat
”.egasuas no tes traeh ym tog ev’I ,lleW“
,xof eht otni yaw eht lla flesmih devohs eH
rednu demriuqs lakcaj ehT
,azzip eht revo dessap dna srallod evif eht koot ehS ”.og uoy ereH“
.wonk ot uoy tnaw I ebyam ,lleW“
”.sliaf reven ybdnats egelloc dlo doog ehT“
”?tnaw uoy tahw wonk uoY“
.xof eht otni nwod flesmih demmals lakcaj ehT
.nwod enohp sih tup oeL
”.yreviled rof kcid a koot tsuj uoY !tihs elttil uoY“
,flesym azzip deredro tsuj evah dluoc I ,haey naem I
.delipmoc xelA ,yltneidebO
slangiS tnedissiD ygolohtna eht detide eh dna
,hcuoc eht no kcab gnihcterts ,xof eht dias ”,ebyam lleW“
”azziP rof gnixoF“ saw sihT
.rood eht ot revo deklaw dna elbat eeffoc eht ffo tellaw eht dehctans eH
”.ekorb llits m’I dna ,nuf on era uoY“ .detuop xof ehT
”.neht uoy rof taem oN“
.taht ecrofnier ot neht dnuos gnilworg a edam hcamots sih dna
”,yob doog a s’tahT“
?yas uoy t’ndluow ,nuf erom tol a saw siht tub
.derewol srae s’xof ehT
,sinep s’lakcaj eht fo esab eht ekat ot dehcaer dna
,gnivarc saw eh tahw yltcaxe mih dlot dah noitanigami siH
.hcuoc eht no raewrednu eht dessot dna
.nirg a htiw xof eht dias
”.doof tuoba gnimaerd tsuJ .gnihton ,hu hO“
.ebul fo elttob eht nepo ot pu tis ot dah
.dnik ni dednopser tnecs nwo sih wenk xelA
.esnopser ni ylwols pu eugnot sih gniward
.tfahs s’lakcaj eht pu dekcil eugnot A
”,uoy raeh ot srobhgien eht tnaw I“
.dnuorg eht tsniaga cirbaf eht gninnip yb
”.ysub teg retteb uoy nehT“
”.yreviled emos teg syawla nac eW“
.ruf sih hguorht gnizarg sgnaf s’lakcaj eht
”.uoy htiw azzip a gnittilps fo gnimaerd tsuj saw I tub ,haeY“
”azziP rof gnixoF“:yojne esaelP
.mih ta nwod dekool oeL
”.taht evol ot gniog er’uoY
.yadirF llit diap teg t’nod I .won thgir ekorb fo dnik m’I“ .denworf xof ehT
”?tnaw uoy od azzip fo epyt tahw ,yawynA
”?taht si kcuf eht tahW ’?ssendoog yseehc ruoy htiw em lliF’“
.tfahs eht no elkcus ot detrats eh sa
rettiwt no gnitirw sih tuoba erom dnif nac uoY .floW-pilS htiw
.retal taht tuoba yrrow d’yeht
”.yojne ot uoy rof taem fo eceip a tsuj m’I ,suoicsnocbus ruoy ot gnidroccA
.deknilb lakcaj ehT
.deddon lakcaj ehT
desuma dekrab lakcaj ehT
,ti od ot tnaw t’ndid eh taht ton
”.yrgnuh m’I tuB“ .denihw xof ehT
”.nwod ti evil em tel t’now uoy dna ,emit eno ti ekat I .emit enO“
.azzip sih teg ot taem emos teg ot evah ot gniog saw eh wonk t’ndid eh tub
”?dranoeL rof skrow egral enO“
.tonk eht tsniaga gut dna
”.etsat yna evah t’nseod ti ro ytlas oot rehtie si ffuts tahT“
.mih revo dehsaw elzzum s’xof eht morf htaerb mraw eht sa denedrah ti ylwolS
,taeH dna GNAF ekil seigolohtna ni deraeppa sah krow ’seyEthgiN
.won srexob sih fo tuo gnikeep saw dna htaehs sih fo eerf deppils dah ssenelam nwo sih dna
.trihs s’oeL no muc gnitteg
.enipluv eht ekorts ot wap denekcils ebul sih gnisu
.yadretsey shtnom xis txen eht rof ecnarusni rac ym yap ot dah I
troffe sih ni remrif werg lakcaj eht litnu detsiser eh tub ,yawa mih dehsup oeL yltneG
”.elppaenip ekil od I ,yeH“
.enohp sih no deppat tsuj oeL ”,huh hU“
”.oot od uoy kniht I“
.seye sih dellor xof ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.pit a rof yenom tuo gnillup
”.ti droffa t’ndluoc uoy dias uoY“
.huh hU“ ”.egasuas saw ereht llew …hU“
,spih sih delggiw xof ehT
.ylkciuq oot raf oot lakcaj eht hsup ot gnitnaw ton
”.naiiawaH gnitteg m’I“
,hcuot sih ta borht yltneg ti gnileef
”.nialpmoc t’now uoy tub
.spil sih dekcil eh ”…yawynA
erow xelA sexob eht fo meh eht nwod deggut eH
.tsrif noertaP sih no deraeppa taht yrots yllis ylgnideecxe na
.xob azzip a gnidloh ,ereht saw nooccar a
”.kcab uoy yap ot yppah eb
# ”!nam pu ekaw ,yeh ,yeH“
”.osla egasuas tuoba gnihtemos draeh I .haey ,haeY“
”.nemar doog ekam ot ffuts eht evah t’nod I tub ,ecin si nemaR
.sdnah sih dnuora depparw trihs-t eht tsniaga gniggut
.dnuos gnihcleuqs a htiw esool emac tI
”.revird eht pit ot tnedicca yb tellaw ruoy debbarg I“ ”?haeY“
,ni flesmih decrof lakcaj eht dna ,koot ti lla saw tahT ”!ris seY“
”.wonk uoy taht htiw elbuort ni em teg uoY“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”?I t’nod ,laem ym nrae ot tog ev’I
.noitapicitna ni deggaw liat siH
.detnap xof eht ”…dog hO“
.srexob sih hguorht gniwohs no-drah a dah eh neht gnizilaer ,ti nethgiarts ot trihs sih dellup dna pu tas xof ehT
.tnap a htiw oeL dias
”?gnireffo uoy era tahw dnA“
,mih tsniaga tonk sih gnihsup
”?egasuas ruoy tnaw uoy yaw ylno eht taht sI“ .mih
.nellows llits tonk sih
.roolf eht morf pu gnitteg ,xof eht dias ”,haeY“
”.oot driew elttil a teg eniM
”,ti klim dna tfahs ym dnuora hctiwt uoy leef ot tnaw I ,no emoC“
.sllib rallod-ytnewt owt tuo dellup dna tellaw eht tuo dleh lakcaj ehT ”.yako s’taht ,hO“
”.tae ew erofeb tsrif pu naelc dluohs ew ebyaM“
.kcab meht dellup dna
”…mM“ ”?hguor elttil a ti ekil t’nod uoy gniyas era uoY“ ”.sdoog
.VT eht fo tnorf ni gur aera eht no nirg a htiw kcab gniyl ,derumrum eh
”?pu em tes tsuj …uoy diD“
”.ti tuoba gnikniht llitS“