”.dias eh ’!ffo ssa ruoy looc lliw
revaeb eht ta detniop htieK
.sessalg sih hguorht detniuqs eh sa deworruf worb s’revaeb ehT
.deksa eh ”?lufituaeB uoy llac tsuj I naC“
.moor gnivil eht fo edis rehto eht no pu tes dah eh rab llams eht ot denruter htieK
”.llet ot drah s’ti ,ruf hcum os evah seilloC uoY
.elbatrofmocnu rehtar dekool ylneddus eilloC elamef ehT  ”!ffuR  !ffurrR
”.tnaw uoy fi ti esu nac uoY“
.goD gnidaeH eht deksa ”?siht s’tahW“
yllaivoj gnisrevnoc erew selam owt ehT
.ti otni edanomel emos deruop dna
”,kcuf ot moordeb ruoy ot pu tnew yeht kniht I“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.llams elttil a erew stit reh thguoht I“
,sliatkcoc wef a gnixif retfA
.knis eht otni sessalg gniknird dna sehsid ytrid eht elip aihtnyC depleh htieK
.htieK dedulcnoc ”.kciR s’taht ,haeY“
.htieK dias ”,em tsurT“
.daeh sih koohs htieK
.spil sih dekcil retseL
.raehrevo ot retseL rof hguone duol saw tnemmoc
?gniod uoy era tahW“
”,retseL ,knird ruoy
.eilloC baNcM a s’eh ,drocer eht rof dna“
:flesmih detouq retseL
.pu depparw dah ytrap ehT
.noitarepsaxe suoivbo htiw dias htieK
,ybraen doots eécnaif s’ekeZ elihw
,nwod denael htieK
,lrig eilloC dedraeB eht ot dias dna
.elamef dedneffo eht morf yawa tnedor eht dereets eh sa dias htieK
”?meht ecudortni uoy t’nod yhW“  .ylmrif dias ehs
”.ssob doog a si caM
”?meht denioj I fi dnim d’yeht kniht uoy oD“
.ffo deklats dna elzzum eht ssorca retseL deppals htoomS eht ,drow a tuohtiW
”?eilloC elamef taht ot em gnicudortni tuoba woh“
”.flesreh yb lla gnidnats eilloC hguoR trohs ehT“
,nosmadA ekeZ saw mih ediseb gnittiS
seirots ’susrU fo selpmas erom dnif nac uoY .moc.skooB-
,tuo dekrab dna seninac owt eht ta dennirg eH
,dias eh ”,ybab ,yeH“
.etis noitcurtsnoc eht fo egde eht ta dekrap
”.detivni t’nerew uoy ,retseL“
.knird driht sih ffo dehsilop dah retseL ,sriatsnwoD
”.lleh sa ynnuf si enil taht ,drocer eht roF
.nwod yaw eht lla seog eugnot siht ,ragus yeH“
4102 ni modnaf yrruf eht derevocsid ohw
.ytrap eht tuoba ekeZ gnillet uoy draehrevo I“
”,ydaerla ti ni kcos a tup ,retseL“  ”!ffur-ffuR“
.seilloC dna sdneirF
.tnedicni eht dessentiw ohw ybraen gnidnats elpuoc eilloC redroB a ot dekool revaeb ehT
.yenoB dias ”,yug nuF“
”,servueo’d sroh fo etalp rehtona eraperp og ot deen I“
”.thginot ereht ni gnipeels era I dna ydniC“
.selaT erooM retseL !nmaD revaeB
.sriats eht nwod tort nisuoc driht ro dnoces s’efiw sih dehctaw htieK
.niaga moor eht ssorca dekool htieK
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
srosicni gib sih fo tnorf eht ssorca eugnot sih nar retseL  ❖  .dias eh
”,gniht eruS“  .dias eh
”?ereh gniod uoy era lleh eht tahW
”?pu yaw eht lla og sgel esoht oD
❖ ❖ ❖  ”.hcnub a sknahT  .ereht eb ll’eW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.dehs eht ni t’nsi doow s’revaeb siht fo tsom taht wonk ot ekil thgim uoY  !yenoh ,yeH“
,srats eht ta pu dekool
,htieK dias ”,ydniC“
”.sknird erom emos xif ot tog ev’I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
koob eht morf tprecxe na si elat sihT
,bonk eht rof dehcaer eh sa tsuJ
.elam htooms a morf klat htooms emos esu dluoc ehs ekil dekool taht
,talf-flah dial srae s’god ehT
.roolf reppu eht ot del hcihw sriats eht ot denrut
”.ecnis reve ti tuoba em gnildeen neeb s’eH“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”?loop ym ni gniod uoy era tahW“  ”.yrroS“
”.sttim llabesab fo ezis eht swaP  .srae yppolF
”,em sekil ehs kniht I“
”.lap ,sdneirf retrohs emos deen uoY
.gniws lluf ni saw ytrap eht dna thgie ot retrauq a saw tI
❖  .daeh sih dnuora stibro owt ylno retfa dedaf was eh srats ehT
”?uoy ot eil I dluoW“
esuoh eht dehcaer retseL ,tnemom taht tA
.moor eht ssorca gnitniop ,detsisni retseL ”,eno tahT“
”seilloC dna sdneirF“
.retnuoc nehctik eht no delip erew redniamer eht ,moor fo tuo nar yeht nehW
.gnileer tnedor eht tfel taht pals a htiw esool tel elamef ehT
.retaw eht revo tuo wap a dednetxe eninac ehT  ”.ydniC evah I  .ti deen t’now I tub“
.redluohs sih revo doow fo parcs pu-dewehc eht dessot revaeb ehT
.mih ediseb pu deppets ohw ,efiw sih yb detpurretni saw god ehT
.deffuh htieK  ”?aniT s’ohW“
.tseug sih demrofni htieK ”,setihw gge oN“
”?I t’nia ,eugaelloc a m’I
ria fo htaerb a rof dray kcab eht otni tuo deppets neht
”.moordeb ym ni xes evah dluow ellehciM dna ekeZ taht tbuod ylsuoires I ,sediseB  .ytrap eritne eht ot ti ecnuonna ot evah t’nod uoy tub“
.llah sriatspu eht ni teiuq saw llA
.yllufepoh dias revaeb eht
❖  .stnap s’revaeb eht fo tnorf eht nwod
.dnah ni servueo’d sroh fo etalp a htiw yb deklaw aihtnyC nehw
.ydob sih morf yawa ti dellup dna
?huh ,seilloC dna sdneirF“
,roolf dnuorg eht no smoor eht dnuora kool lanif eno dah
.loop eht fo tuo pleh s’htieK detpecca eh sa deksa retseL
”?uoy od ,ereh gnir a ees t’nod uoY“
.selam owt eht ot pu deklaw aihtnyC ,tnemom taht tA
.lednafniZ fo ssalg a gnippis
”?deb ruoy ni gnikcuF“
.thginot hcuoc eht no gnipeels eb d’eh fi gnirednow mih tfel taht kool a dnabsuh reh dehsalf dah aihtnyC
.llew sa detneserper erew sdeerb detaler rehto wef a tuB
,eilloC hguoR eht dias ”,sknahT“
.lap ,ysae ti ekaT  !hseeY“
.yenoB ,emoclew er’uoy ,hU“
a drocer eht rof dnA
,tuo hsart eht koot htieK
”,srats eht ta gnikooL
”…sdneirf elamef elgnis ruoy fo emos ot retseL ecudortni nac uoy ebyam“
”.noitnetta ta gnidnats setavirp ym evah uoy esuaceB
.roolf niam eht ot tnecsed sih nageb eh sa
.elamef eht dias ”,sseug I ,hU“
.doog denmad s’eh tub
❖  .rood moordeb eht dniheb morf tnecca dnalaeZ weN tcnitsid a htiw nekops
”,ereh eilloC-non ylno eht ton m’I ees I“
.tcnitsni nailammam cisab tsom ruo si gnitaM
”?yug nuf A  ?retseL“
,sgel sih neewteb liaT
woble eht yb rekrowoc sih koot htieK
”.thginot hcuoc ym no peels nac uoY
.sessalgeye kciht sih hguorht gnitniuqs ,moor eht dnuora dekool revaeb ehT
.demialcxe eh ”!azwoY“
”?aidyL  ?eman-reh-s’tahw gnitad uoy t’nerA“
elam desitsahc eht
”.eilloC hguoR a saw I taht mih demrofni dna
.toob krow sih evoba elkna sih fo ruf erab eht gnilaever pu stnap sih fo gel eht dellup eh ,eerf dnaH
?melborp eht s’tahw ,yeH“
?mih dnif uoy d’erehW
.eilloC a em dellac retseL
?retseL“  .deknilb htieK
,retseL dias ”,sdeerb god no trepxe on m’I wonk I“  ”.eilloC
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.retal sraey owt seires noisiviD gnoL
,ytterP“  .ylpeed delahni dna
”oot em“ sdrow eht raeh ot llah eht ni tfel eno on saw erehT
retseL“  .deksa ehs ”?dneirf ruoy s’ohW  .yenoh ,yeH“
.stros lla fo seilloC htiw dekcap saw esuoh nosraC ehT
.noihsaf ekil-eninac tsomla na ni
.thgin no na dah reve dneirf tnedor sih nehw derednow htieK  .revaeb eht dias
”.erehpsimeh nrehtuos eht ni ksum eht lla ekil sllems moor tahT“  .htieK dias ”,haeY“
”,werc eht no keew tsrif ruoy devivrus uoy oS“
?rood eht dniheb morf gnimoc dnuos gnitnap a raeh eh did ro
.hcrop eht otno gnidael sriats tfihsekam eht debmilc dna
stseug sih rof sknird gnixim saw htieK
.ylsuoiverp deppals dah nisuoc eilloC htoomS reh taht eno eht etisoppo ecaf sih fo edis eht no saw ti retseL rof ylikcuL
”.moorhtab eht ot pu nur ot deen I“  .deremmats htieK ”…hu ,I“
”?gniht ’ffur-ffur‘ eht htiw s’tahW“  ”.boj
”!enola nemow deirram eht evael ot uoy denraw I  !retseL ,goD“
”?dnah s’aniT no gnir eht ees uoy t’ndiD“
”seilloC dna sdneirF“ saw sihT
niaga ecno bonk rood sih rof dehcaer eilloC hguoR ehT
tnemeerga ni gniddon saw htieK
.flesruoy evaheb ot yrt dna knird ruoy knird woN
”.aihtnyC ,efiw ym teem dna ni emoc ,retseL“
.ydniC htiw gnittahc won saw dna selam owt eht morf flesreh devomer dah eipleK nailartsuA eht tub
.sgod fo kcap a ekil llems t’ndid taht
.tey koob enohp eht ni t’nera uoy dna sserdda ruoy evah t’ndid I“
cificeps eb ot mih dlot I
sih gnitirw nageb dna
”!ekeZ ,skcos raew t’nod I“
.wap tfel sih pu dleh retseL
.reffo eht deredisnoc dna epolevne eht morf drac a dellup ekeZ
.moordeb retsam eht edistuo desuap htieK
,kcab daeh sih detlit eilloC hguoR ehT
.sriatsnwod uoy ees ll’I ,yeH“
.tnecca evitcnitsid sih ni hciwdnas fo lufhtuom a dnuora delbmum ekeZ ”,haeY“
?adnohR ot taht yas yllaer uoy diD“
”.revo em gnivah rof sknahT  !ytrap taerG“
.ssalg s’revaeb eht otni daD dnarG dlO fo tohs a tuo gnirusaem nageb eh sa htieK dias
tsoh ytrap eht dellac ”!gnimoc m’I ,haeY“
”?ela regnig erom yna tog uoY“
.thgin worromot ecalp ruo ta ytrap a gnivah era I dna ydniC
!god ykcul eno era uoy ,htieK“
.flesmih deksa eh
.gel nekcihc dloc a dnuora
”.won sraey owt revo elttil a rof mih htiw gnikrow neeb ev’I
”.ees I tahw ekil I dna eno ees I nehw eilloC ’redaorB‘ a wonk I tub“
s’ereH“  .wap sih otni ruos yksihw a desserp ohw
morf liof munimula fo parw a deleep eh sa ekops htieK
s’ekeZ  ”?skcos fo riap dlo na sa nihT“  ”.tiuq ot nehw wonk t’nseod tsuj dna niht ekoj ’ffur-ffur‘ diputs taht nrow s’eH  !goD“
.su nioj ot uoy ekil d’eW
.ffo yrd dna ni no emoc ,ereH“
.flah ni uoy kaerb t’ndid kciR ykcul er’uoY“
.skooB-DL morf snoitide cinortcele dna kcabrepap ni elbaliava si seires noisiviD gnoL eritne ehT
”?moor tseug eht teg tsael ta I t’noD“
,lla dna eci ,liatkcoc reh fo redniamer eht depmud yltpmorp ehs nehT
sihT‘  .ni em werht yug gib tahT“
.gniteerg ni dnah a dednetxe ehs sa ssetsoh eht dias ”,ydniC em llac esaelP“
tsoh sih fo ecnaraeppa eht yb detpurretni saw retseL
.no em gnittup eb ot tog ev’uoy tub“
.ydal eilloC hguoR desserd-llew eht dias ”?yllaeR“
.no gnittih tsuj erew uoy eilloC redroB eht si aniT“
,ekeZ htiw gnittahc llits saw retseL
.su rof snalp rehto yna sah ellehciM kniht t’nod I
.gnirats saw retseL taht noitcerid eht ni kool ot denrut htieK
”?.C.C uoy llac I fi dnim uoy od ,yeH  .ma I ,seY
”?uoy lliw ,nwod ti peeK  !retseL ,goD“
.daeh sih fo sedis eht morf yawa tuo gnikop
?seugaelloc dna sdneirf rof saw ytrap eht yas uoy t’ndiD  ?t’nsaw I“
elkcub tleb s’retseL rof dehcaer ehS  ”.ees s’teL“
.spil sih dekcil retseL
”,thgin ffo na gnivah saw I“  ”.flah
noitanigami sih ti saW
”.retseL fo eceip a rof pu denil evah nemow deirram fo tol
.smrahc sih htiw oow ot elamef a fo hcraes ni ffo tes retseL
.ti fo kcab eht dessik dna wap s’aihtnyC koot revaeb ehT
.noitangiser ni dehgis dna elpmet sih debbur htieK
.thgieh ym s’taht ereh eno ylno eht s’eh ,em esucxe ,eno ylno eht s’ehS  !nmad dnA“  ”…retseL“
,sotcrA susrU yb
”,skcos raew t’nod I ,drocer eht roF“
ll’tahW“  .pu ti dleh dna ssalg a ni eci emos tup god ehT
.tseug detivninu eht dias ”,erooM
.moordeb eht morf emoc elggig gnidnuos-elamef a raeh dluoc eh erows htieK
”.krow ta werc noitcurtsnoc ym no si retseL ,hU“  ”!toir a s’eH
”…tegrof I erofeb ,yeH“
”!NMAD tub ,revaeb a ton er’uoy wonk I“
.eninac rehto eht ot dias htieK
”.krow morf s’htieK fo dneirf a m’I“
,dias eh ”,sdeerb god no trepxe on m’I“
,oN“  ”?knird a flesym xif I fi dniM
”.tros emos fo reirreT a gnieb mih no saw yenom yM  ?eilloC a s’tahT
.dessih eninac eht ”!deirram s’ehS
.elkcuhc ot nageb eH
,tcatnoc edam sregnif sih erofeb tub
.sdeerb god tuoba noissucsid a gnivah erew su fo emos ,oga skeew elpuoc A“
?eeS“  .rekrowoc sih ot denrut retseL
”?efiw sih ot gnihtemos yas uoy diD“
,haeY  ?kcolc’o neveS
.eipleK nailartsuA evitcartta na ,eécnaif sih htiw pu nwohs dah goD gnidaeH eht dna
”?ruos yeksihW“  ”?evah uoy
pukcip retsevraH lanoitanretnI na drawot gnilddaw saw ohw revaeb a ta regnif a detniop ekeZ
.xob hcnul sih denepo dna hcrop kcab eht fo egde eht no tas nosraC htieK  0591 tsuguA  sotcrA susrU yb
,ekeZ ot ylteiuq dias dna revo denael htieK
.ecnayonna ni denettalf srae s’htieK
!revaeb taht dna“ ,baNcM eht dias ”,haey ,hO“
.enip fo parcs a no gniwang ylisub dna dnah ni xob hcnul a htiw yaw rieht gnidaeh saw ohw
?emit doog a gnivah uoy erA“
”.liam eht ni tsol tog noitativni ym sseug I
.ssalg ytpme na htiw rab eht ot denruter retseL ,retal emit emoS
”?yddub ,llifer a tuoba woH“
!nosraC ydniC“ ,delims dna
?elihw a rof mih ot klat og uoy t’nod yhW  .ereht revo si ekeZ ,kooL
,sotcrA susrU yb
.eilloC dedraeB a yb dlot ekoj a ot esnopser ni dehgual eh sa deggaw liat debbob siH
”?noitnetta ta setavirP
”?thgir ,emoclew m’I ,dneirf a sA
a pu kcuf mih nees reve ev’I yas t’naC  .tsaf skroW
.eninac rehto eht ot tuo ti dleh dna xob hcnul sih fo tuo epolevne llams a dellup eilloC hguoR eht
”.hguoht ,retseL fo ekam ot tahw erus ton m’I“
,redluohs s’tsoh sih revo kool a htiw retseL dias ”,xes fo gnikaepS“
.loop gnimmiws draykcab sih drawot denrut dna depmuj htieK  ”?ti t’nsi
.ten.ytiniffaruf no
”.retseL ,knird a uoy ruop em teL“
.revaeb eht dias ”,yddub ,yako s’tI“
”.seL ,seilloC dna sdneirf rof saw ti dias I“
”,etal m’I yrroS  .yddub ,ereht yeH“
gnixim saw eh liatkcoc eht morf pu dekool htieK
.tnedor gib eht dias
,htoomS dna hguoR erew ytirojam ehT
.yletilop deksa ehs ”?emit ecin a gnivah uoy era ,retseL“
”.hcuoC“  ”?tahW“  ”!retseL“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.’eh‘ a si ’ehs‘ ,drocer eht rof dna godpeehS dnaltehS a si“ ,dias htieK ”,tahT“
.rae s’revaeb eht morf hcni na eson detniop ,gnol sih
,htieK dias ”,yenoB s’tahT“
,eilloC hguoR eht delworg ”,os ebyaM“
”…hu ,meht tuoba thgir erew uoY“  .htieK dias
”?ekeZ ,thgirla gniod uoY“
,dnah ni knird hserF
”.ti seod ydobyrevE
”.taht ekil gnihtemoS  .nisuoc driht ro dnoceS  .wohemos ydniC ot detaler s’eH“
.kcab ym no gnitaolF“
.rood tnorf eht ot moor gnivil sih ni stseug fo stonk eht hguorht yaw sih demrow tsoh ehT
.deilper htieK ”,noitativni nA“
,gniyonna ytterp eb nac retseL“
,elihw a rof melborp s’esle ydobemos erooM retseL ekam ot deveileR
.roloc-irT“  ”?kciR naem uoY“
.yltcaf-fo-rettam ,dias retseL
.aihtnyC morf yawa mih dereets dna
”.gnola lrig ruoy gnirB
,esuoh eht retne ot denrut retseL sA
”,ereht ni era ellehciM dna ekeZ“  ”?moor ruoy toN“
.hciwdnas mah sih fo flah nwod dewohc ydaerla dah
.redroB dna dedraeB
.esuops sih demrofni eh ”,ti tog ev’I“
.llebrood eht fo dnuos eht ta deleviws srae sih nehw
”.emit doog a gnivah er’uoy dalg m’I
,stnannep ralugnairt owt
”seilloC dna sdneirF“   yojne esaelP
.god etihw-dna-kcalb eht dias ”!htieK ,yeH“
”!em fo tuo parc eht deracs uoY  !retseL ,goD“
.spil sih dekcil dna yldlob reh ot pu deklaw eH
.riaf s’eh tub ,drah hsup nac eH“  .deddon htieK
.enot gninraw a htiw dias eh ”…seL“
.eilloC suoecavruc eht drawot gnilddaw ydaerla saw revaeb eht tuB
guj somrehT sih fo pac eht dewercsnu htieK
.daeh sih koohs eH
.dneirf sih ta dekool retseL
.tuo deppets eilloC baNcM a dna denepo mih etisoppo rood moorhtab eht
.ekeZ detacol dah retseL taht demrifnoc ecnalg kciuq A
.taerg neeb evah syug eht lla dna krow eht yojne I“
.hgual rehtona htiw tuo dellac tnedor gib eht
esruoc fo ekeZ saw erehT
.sriatsnwod morf detuohs yenoB ”!htieK ,yeH“
?tnaegres llird a uoy erA“
.”me‘ tuohtiw evil nac I  .yako s’tahT“
ssetsoh sih ecaf ot denrut retseL
”.flesruoy pleH  .lla ta ton
”.tneve launna na siht ekam ot deen eW“
.werc noitcurtsnoc eht no eibwen eht
.hgual a htiw dias retseL
.eilloC redroB elamef yltrop a ta detniop saw hcihw eson s’tnedor eht dewollof dna
”.rab eht morf tuo uoy gnikcehc saw I“ ,dias eh
”?eilloC elamef tahW“
.trihs naiiawaH lufroloc a ni desserd elam etihw-dna-kcalb a ta bmuht sih dekrej eh sa retseL dias
eilloC htoomS elamef a dnuof eH
”,ydal ytterp ,ereht yeH“
.nehctik eht fo noitcerid eht ni ffo gnidaeh erofeb esuops reh ot dias ydniC ”,retsim tol a sknahT“
”?ecalp tsrif eht ni ereht ni teg uoy did woh dna no sehtolc ruoy htiw ereht ni gniod uoy era tahw naem I“
”?ellehciM dna ekeZ ot deneppah tahW
,dias dna dnabsuh reh ta delims ehS
goD gnidaeH dnalaeZ weN ehT
.revaeb eht deilper
daeh sih detlit revaeb ehT
”.olos gniylf ot desu m’I“
.hcrop sih no gnidnats revaeb railimaf a dnif ot ti denepo eH
.daeh sih fo pot eht dehctarcs eilloC ehT  ”?yug giB“
.eil uoy draeh reven ev’I tub ,retseL ,sgniht fo tol a er’uoY“
.ffo deliart eciov s’god elam ehT