",hsifles ton dna yloh erew snoitnetni ruoy devorp ev'uoY" .deksa I
.tnaw uoy knird ro doof yna uoy gnirb ll'I
.ti ni dessip dah sbuc egalliv eht fo wef a retfa
,lla ta toN !oN ?ralgrub A"
!fmM" .ti deruoved I
.yaw sih no mih dnes dna dlog ni
,renroc eht dnuor emac diam yrellucs s'raciv ehT
,hpmuirt ni yelehtarC ssorca
.xiorCaL esoR yb ”arcaS
,yldnuos tpels dna noitsuahxe ni despalloc smirglip emos elihW
".gnosnevE ecnis neeb s'ti tsemlac eht si sihT
.tfarchctiw fo em esucca dna
,srae s'pohsib eht dehcaer klat taht fo yna fI
,kcab-ot-tnorf erew eW
"!tneconni em ees lliw doG .llew yreV"
.niaga gniyrt yb esol ot gnihton dah I
;taht retfa pu evag I
.yawrood eht gnikcolb
.eye eno revo egadnab a htiw
gniht elgnis a knird ron
,erauqs eht hguorht degdurt I sa
,em rof ciler eht eveirter ll'uoy fI"
,htuom ym tsniaga egnops dloc a ot ekow I
.yaw gnol a delevart ev'I tub erom klat ot evol d'I ,em evigroF" .dias yraM
mamina taidotsuc itsirhC useI irtson inimod siugnas te suproC" .ecilahc egral yrev a ni
.ruoh na naht erom rof egaraciv eht edistuo neerg eht no decap dna delffuhs I
,noitcelfer peed ni rehto eht dna
,droN fo tsom hguorht
nepo edis eno htiw gge nedlog a ekil depahs
-eman sih saw sordoweT -aneyh eht tsael tA
,teef owt nwo ym no dnats ot elba ylerab saw I
",won stnias eht htiw s'eH" .nageb I
.mrots a ni eid t'nod uoy epoh dna
etag eht gnikcolnu ,dias raciv eht
”,yrubswerhS ot og ot elbuort hcum taht ton s'ti tub
.yenoh dna regnig fo dellems taht egareveb toh a
;llew dne t'ndid pirt tahT  .yravlaC morf
thgilnus thgirb fo stfahS
drawrof degrus dworc eht ;kcul oN
",taht od t'nac eW"
.flesym revo ssorc eht fo ngis eht gnikam ,dias I
.retsiolc cihtoG lufituaeb a htiw dednapxe neeb dah dna
,noixificurC eht fo lepahC eht otni lesihc a gniyrrac enoyna ot yldnik ekat t'ndid sralpmeT eht
.gnipeels woleb nwod t'nsaw eh nehw
stseirp fo puorg a ees ot gnitcepxe
.delworg hcamots yM
,egroeG .tS ot reyarp a reffo ot emoc ev'eW"
,swehpen ym ot uoy ecudortni ot togrof I
.daeh sih koohs xof ehT "!gnitsaf m'I"
,samleahciM txen yb kcab ton er'uoy fI"
"!nosielE eiryK"
.tuo yrc t'ndid I tub
".mahtnarG fo notsniW
"!gnah em ees ot detnaw eH
.denruter diam yrellucs ehT
.siht detanod xessE fo ssetnuoC eht dneirf yM“
,sciler dna senirhs erofeb gniyarp
xiorCaL esoR yb ”arcaS atruF“
cinut neerg a ni retto na dias ",dneirf ,wonk t'nod I"
.gnihtyna rof deksa evah dluoc I tniop taht tA
,namreG woL dna hgiH
yloh gnieb deppots retaw yloh eht nehw stnof lamsitpab ni demrof taht puos eliv eht ekil dellems tI
...m'I" .knas traeh yM ".deid
",atlaM ot og dna yenom eht ekat
ll'eH" .retal stnemom wef a denruter lrig yrellucs ehT
,egroeG .tS fo enirhs eht dnuor gnikaenS
yrlavihc fo redro tsewol taht morf
?saerdnA rehtorB hctef ot em tnaw uoy oD"
etah fo lluf seye
"!ti dibrof I naidotsuc lepahc sA" .dias eh
.gnuts yletulosba
,retal setunim wef a emac saerdnA nehW
,ratla eht ta devirra I emit eht yB
;oga sraey evif-ytnewt
"!ssenisub tnegru si siht ,ti tuoba kciuq eB"
.etag eht fo pot eht ot flesym detsioh I
thgirb detniap llah taerg a otni ecnartne s'tnavres eht koot eW
"?siht naht retteb eb ylbissop dluoc tahW"
.nepo rood yrellucs eht draeh I
,edistuo erauqs eht was I lardehtac eht tfel I sA .ti edam I tuB
.sdrowllipS no dehsilbup yltnecer saw sretcarahc namuh htiw yrots siht fo noisrev A
,esruoc fo ,stseirp ehT
.acilisab namoR a ekil
.elggurts a saw pets yrevE
yawrood eht ni toof detoob a devohs I
?tsael ta serif nehctik ruoy yb flesym mraw dna ni emoc I thgiM"
.rehto eht ot toof eno morf ydob sseltser ym gnitfihs ,deirc I
.sgnirps no fi sa ,tuhs deppans rood ehT
.hcruhc noxaS dlo eht ot yawdim etag eht hguorht
esuoh eht fo tuo em deggard mailliW dna eh dna
.wollof ot em rof gnirutseg
,dnah thgir ym ni dehctulc yrauqiler eht htiw ,dna
.tenalpruF yb dehsilbup htob
,kao elgnis a morf devrac
detalsnart si egroeG .tS fo ciler siht litnu tsoh noinummoc eht rof tpecxe
.sseniltnias ym fo emos pu kaos ot gniyrt
.em erofeb sevlesmeht dessorc dna tlenk dworc ehT .deirc enoemos
.noS yM ,yawa thgiR"
,did yeht esruoc fo dnA
.dellac I ",notsniW ,em s'tI"
kced eht no deklus dna em ot ylrus saW -eman sih saw dnarreF -thgink ehT
",sgnah eh erus ekam dna setartsigam eht ot mih ekat
nodnoL morf tibbar suovren a
",melasureJ ot yaw ym no ,hguorht gnissap ylno m'I
”arcaS atruF“ saw sihT
.ees ot hguone thgirb dewolg ecalp eht litnu
.dnats ylerab dluoc I
"!walc eht laets ot deirt eH" .deralced
knom xof eht yawa gnihsup
.deksa ehs "?ralgrub ehT
# ".sselb doG" .yraM dias
traeh sti tA .modnetsirhC fo stsoptuo tsehtruf eht fo eno dna
,nwogthgin klis a ni desserd
",ecarG ruoY ,eveels sih pu ti dah ylraen eH"
.daeh sih koohs dna smra sih dessorc raciv ehT
.delworg lrig yrellucs eht
,sgel aes sih dah dna delevart-llew saw eH
.yrruh a ni saw I
;rehtie thgin yb ciler taht ot esolc gnitteg on saw erehT
.esrup nioc a ot nikseniw a morf knurhs dah hcamots yM
!deificurc saw roivaS eht erehw kcor yrev ehT
.derumrum dworc ehT ".yal
",rehtaF ,thgirla etiuQ"
.klis etihw detliuq htiw edisni denil
sdaeb yrasor sih
.rood eht tsniaga thgiew ym gnisserp
sesuoh sa llat sa sevaW
.yaw ym no tae ot gnihtemos em evig dnA"
”.uoy fo sekil eht orf teg reve dluoc I gnihtyna naht retteB
"!uoy rof ti evah ll'I ,ti emaN
,renroc yaw-eht-fo-tuo na ni llaw a tsniaga depmuls dna
,esoh deroloc-krad
.sessorc htiw detarofrep nretnal ssarb a gniyrrac
,deksa retto eht "?yrgnuh uoy erA"
!em fo edur woh ,notsniW ,hA"
"!sgnoleb ti erehw
.erom yna romra gniraew t'nsaw
.sregnif etaciled sih neewteb gnilddiwt
.wodahs peed ni moor eht fo srenroc eht gnivael
.derumrum I ",thgirlA"
.feiht ciler lanoisseforp a gnirih fo ymehpsalb eht no yenom sih etsaw t'ndid ro
.egattop dloc rieht deppis yeht elihw srehtorb eht fo tnorf ni thgir eugnot ym htiw esaerg eht pu pols dna
.dlrow eht fo renroc yreve ylraen tuoba yrots a dah dna
.swollag eht ro atlaM .notsniW ,yrroS"
.meht dniheb ssam gnihtees eht yb drawrof devohs gnieb erofeb ecno ylno walc eht ot htolc fo pirts a gnihcuot hcae
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
frahw eht raen erehwemos yleritne dworc eht tsol I
,suilbuP tniaS" "?ohw tniaS"
",ti raeh ot yrros
.ti hsurc I erofeb rood eht fo tuo toof ruoy ekat dnA"
.redluohs ym no dednal dnah yvaeh ,egral a nehw cinut ym edisni deffuts ti dah ylraen dna
anegicnarF aiV eht nwod klaw s'yad ytfif ro ytrof rehtona s'ti ereht morf dna
.nretnal reh gniyrrac
.spil ym tsap gnilkcirt
"?uoy rof od I yam tahw ,oS"
.atlaM ot detalsnart neeb s'tI"
,yad eht fo dne eht yB
tneb saw kcab sih
kcas eraps a ni yrauqiler eht tup I
syad eerht retfa tuB !kcirp tahT
.seenk dna sdnah ym no lardehtaC eht hguorht devom I
.dne s'tiw ym ta saw I dna
,dnal s'drehpehs a s'tI
.yrauqiler eht erofeb niaga despalloc I
,tsoh desselb eht tub gnihton no syad ytrof rof evil ot gniyrt s'eH
,rehtaF ,timda tsum I“
eson sih pu selcatceps sih dehsup pohsib ehT
,detsetorp I "!ciler siht etalsnart ot emoc ev'I" .dias saerdnA
eerf rof daer ot elbaliava era seirots trohs ylrae reh fo ynam dna
".uoy evigrof ot dediced ev'I dna
,eseehc ,stun ,tiurf
,ti no mals rood eht fo thgiew lluf eht tlef dna
,derrulb noisiv ym ,kaew saw I
"!emoh og em tel dna efil ym erapS
",erom yna yrubswehS ni t'nsi ciler eht ,hO"  .dias I
!stnias gnivil rof devreser saw ronoh taht
.hctac did reven I eman esohw knom taht htiw gnola ,emoR ot yawetag
.kcen ym ta reggad lednor a delevel eh sa
tub tsoh eht no syad ytrof rof evil dluoc ohw
,dedaelp I "!droL hO"
anut eritne na ruoved ot yldab os detnaw I
.yawa ecnatsid trohs a hcruhc eht drawot em gnidael dna
.semit eerht deppar dna rood 'stnavres eht ot dnuor
kram a dna servil xis lacsar siht evig ,yrneH ,mailliW
.nugeb dah nosaes yrd ehT
.yaw siht detaert eb ot evresed t'ndid I woh tuoba
.uoy detaert ew woh rof yrros os m'I"
.dekcol saw etag egaraciv eht emit sihT
.hcruhc dlo gnilbmurc taht xif ot yenom on snaem sgnireffo on dna ,sgnireffo on snaem smirglip oN !gnireffus er'eW
,sroloc htrae elap fo dnalsi na si atlaM
.deid sah pohsiB eht ,noS"
ecineV ot teg uoy litnu
yrauqiler renni eht fo gge dedlig llams eht dehctef saerdnA rehtorB
deciton I nehw saw tahT
?morf emoc uoy od erehW" "!uoy knahT
.ecnelis rof dworc eht ot dnah ym gnisiar
.eboredrag eht ot nar dna
.dnalgnE ot nruter ot elba eb reven d'I dna niaga ciler eht esol dluoc I
,deggeb I "!thginot dloc yrev s'tI
.denmad eht fo stirips eht ekil deirc dniw eht dna
.em niatsus ot hguone ton tub doof fo em dnimer ot hguone ylno saw
.yravlaC fo eceip a s'tI
.esaenu ym gniyarteb liat gnihctiwt ym ,dias I
eniw teews fo stelpord
nomiS ed mailliW riS
yrots trohs reh yltneceR
,sbewboc suortsnom ni derevoc dna ytsud meht fo lla
.gnignis neve ro ,gninid ,gnisrevnoc
.enog saw etiteppa yM
,ehtaerb ot moor yna ylecracs
,detatiseh I fi tuB
.tib a em gnidnah dna
.lla ta ezingocer t'ndid I segaugnal rehto ynam dna ,hsirI dna ,esroN ,namroN
.dereens raciv gnuoy eht
"?teg eh did raf woH"
.yllaicepse saerdnA rehtorB" .delbmurg I
"?kcas eraps a evah ydobyna seoD"
,nwod em derats eh
# .eid dluow I niatrec
tae rehtien llahs I taht ,em ot dias sah droL ehT"
.em ta dewang tsriht dna regnuH
noinummoc eht eviecer ot
.ecarG ruoY ,notsniW"
hsilgnE ni seciov owt draeh I
"!niaga uoy nraw t'now I
,semit eerht nellaf s'eH"
.dnah ni walc desselb eht
.hsilgnE raelc ni deksa eh
.dias raciv eht ",yrros ylbirreT"
.erac t'ndid I tub
.swodahs eht morf eciov peed a dias
.dias eulb ni nexiv eht
,ecnereffidni suoip fo kool a no tup
,yrruh a ni er'uoy fI
;em detseretni taht sciler yna evah t'ndid s'luaP .tS emit eht tA
,sevaw eht no wol gnidir
.meht ot pu deldis I dna
tnip a rof nrevat ybraen a ot yawa deirruh I
.taht retfa yldneirf emaceb
.tuo yaw a fo kniht ot emit fo ytnelp dah I
elffins a hctac dluoc eh os
,em ta kcas gniknalc taf a werht yrneH
,suoreneg yrev er'uoY" ".esac ni tsuj
.hcruhc ruo ot kcab ti gnirb ot uoy deen I
.flesym revo ssorc eht edam dna
yrollaM yraM m'I
.worromot suilbuP .tS fo tsaef eht rof ereh osla er'ew tub
.ti raeh ot yrros yllufdaerD"
sebor s'pohsib a ni xebi dlo nA
...yaw eht fo tuo raf oot eb dluow atlaM ot pirt a diarfa m'I ?atlaM" ".atlaM
"?saerdnA ti si tahW" .mutorcs a ekil dekool taht nihc ybbalf ylddo na dna
ssarb dedlig fo xob delemane na saw ratla eht raeN
;oot swollag eht epacse ot gniyrt ylbaborp saw ohw
"!detalsnart eb ot detnaw ciler taht tuB" .delworg yrneH
,erauqs eht hguorhT
.sdnah ym ni ti decalp dna
.spil ym ot ecilahc eht gnittup erofeb em revo ssorc eht gnikam ,detnahc eh ",nema
rageniv htiw tuc
.don a evag xof ehT
sebor sih fo sdroc eht deit saerdnA rehtorB elihw ecaf ym ni hsif dekoms dna stun dna
evan eht fo dne tsew eht raen
",notsniW ,thgin dooG"
.erofeb yad eht morf regdab eht saw tI
,teef ym ot flesym dellup dna
enots fo eceip a htiw evael ot gnipoh
toc eht fo egde eht no pu tas I
.pu gnittis ,dias I
.teef ym ta dednal skcas riahtaog ytrof tuobA .deksa I
.egnops eht dleh ohw
,elpmaxe rof ,suoip er'uoy fI
,sevaol rof sgab rieht ni gud smirglip ehT ".yaw
,cidrabmoL ,naiteneV
.niatrecnu dna trohs spets sih dna
"!nos ,uoy htiw eb doG !oG"
.nruter htgnerts ym fo emos tlef I
,srenroc nwo rieht ni tas knom eht dna lerdnuocs ehT
"!ereh emoc ot maerd a ni em dlot flesmiH doG"
.retaw on dna daerb oN
.kaolc pmad ym hguorht gniwolb saw dniw psirc a won tub
.sciler rof hcraes ot melasureJ ot yaw ym no
,s'luaP .tS fo rood eht edistuO
,I dna ratla eht raen
,reyarp ni fi sa rehtegot sdnah ym dleh dna pu tas I
",gnikaepS" .dednamed I
"!desselb yrev er'uoY" .dias I ",dnoceS"
.demialcxe I "!olleh ,hA"
"...mre ,neht hturt eht gnillet er'uoy emussa s'teL"
,tpecsnart eht fo renroc eht ta rood worran a ot mra eht yb em gniggard
.drawrof deppets saerdnA
",uoy ees t'nac eh ,lleW"
.setartsigam eht ot revo em dnah ot ni gnigrahc
?ni slwob sih dehsaw eh tahw taht sI
.tsedrah eht erew regnuh fo syad eerht tsrif ehT
",erom yna ti deen t'nod eW"
,tuoba pihs eht dessot
.seert wef htiw ,nerrab dna dira
yrubretnaC morf knom lerriuqs a
"!no og ,lleW"  .ssenkrad kcalb
.thguoht egnarts a dah I nehT
,renroc krad a otni yawa
,htuom ym ni eveels ym gnikaT
,evan eht fo dne raf eht ta enirhs nnA .tS elttiL eht yb revo
"?...elcnu ruoy tuB" .delbmurg yrneH
,artxe servil wef a uoy yap ll'I dnA"
;ssenisub hcruhc emos no emoR ot yaw sih no
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sdrowllipS no dehsilbup osla saw ”sgnihT daB ehT“
,regdab gib a ,redro ni sdworc eht tpek ohw srairf eht fo eno
.tiaw ot evah tsuj ll'uoY"
,erofeb ecno ereht neeb d'I
.slewob ym yb pu em gnirts d'yeht ro etis yloh eht fo eceip ym tuohtiw evael ot dlot saw I dna
?thgin dna yad yretnesyd evah ton raciv taht did woH
,thgin eht otni gnol no deirrac srehto
.em dnuora kaolc ym gniward dna gnirevihs
.nirg a gnilfits ,mih erofeb dewob I
flesym deggard I
.dnalgnE fo serohs eht morf atlaM ot teg ot mirglip a rof syaw lareves era erehT # .dekrab mailliW
.kcen sih tuoba xificurc dedlig egral a dna ,seohs dednuor
atruF“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
,enil eht otni dezeeuqs I emit tsal eht yB
,yad 'suilbuP .tS saw yad txen ehT
.evivrus dluow I woh tuo erugif ot syad eerhT
.tah ym gnignirw ,deilper I
.dam em evord ylraen taht tsriht saw tI
,deksa I ",tuo dloc s'tI
.yaw ym sgniht ees d'uoy thguoht I"
.gel degadnab a dna
,delbmurg tacelop eht
.egroeG .tS fo enirhs eht drawot devohs erew ew litnu ruoh na naht erom rof pu dleh dna
",ciler eht em gnirB"
;ytsur lla si elliam esohw dna hsaw reven ohw
",sgnileef drah oN"
",pirt ruoy fo tsoc eht yap ll'I
,ecilahc eht morf eniw yretaw fo tnip flah a ebyam knurd d'I retfA
yrauqiler depahs-gge llams eht no dnah ym dah I
!drayhcruhc eht ni pu gud sgod eht esproc a ffo ti tog elcnu ym
.weiv fo tuo ylefas ,emit htruof a despalloc dna
.derumrum xof eht
".revo si tsaf ruoY" .dias xof eht
.saerdnA morf yawa gnitsiwt
.deksa pohsib eht
ssenkrad eht ni gnidoorb eno
.uoy htiw laed setartsigam eht tel ll'ew
,erhclupeS yloH eht fo hcruhC eht rof elbuort ym devas I
.elbat eht ta mih morf ssorca taes a gnikat ,dias I
atlaM ni devirra ew
,ydob ym ot sgar gniknits gnihcuot
,tuo dereep sserd nworb nialp a ni tacelop gnuoy A
swodniw yrotserelc eht hguorht
”.enodtuo neeb ev'I
# "!ssel oN !syad ytroF
.em fo retteb eht tog noitsuahxe dna regnuh
.ecneliS .dellac I "!olluH"
",rehtaF ,deednI" "?eerga uoy t'nod
raciv eht ot detfig
.samleahciM litnu syad lareves tog llits ev'ew eveileb I dna ciler eht gnirb did I tuB
,emit htruof a gnilbmuts tuohtiw hcruhc eht fo tuo klaw nac uoy fI .noS ,ereH"
,raciv eht saw erehT
.syad ytneves ot ytfif ni
ecaf denroh sih was I semit wef ehT .devom t'nsaw eh
.yrautcnas eht otni kcab deltsoj saw I dna
,ti no foor dael wen a dah hcruhc noxaS dlo ehT
,elbat eht til eldnac kaew elgnis A
.eriw nedlog yb edisni dleh walc wed s'egroeG .tS dna
.thgin eht rof moor ym
".won retteb hcum gnihtemos tog ev'eW
;elbaknihtnu saw ecilahc eht morf knird em ekil naiffur yranidro na tel oT
.erofeb sraey eerht ylno did ti naht reibbahs dekool egalliv elohw eht tcaf nI
,dias ehs ",yaw siht thgiR"
.elbissop sa drah sa ti ekam ot uoy stnaw eh tub
yrautcnas eht dnuora lla seldnac gnithgil
,erauqs eht hguorhT
,deffuh regdab eht
,noitcafsitas taht mih evig ot desufer I
",tsirhC fo doolb eht dna ydob eht ylno em gnirB" .daeh ym gniwob
-nodnoL morf lerdnuocs eht elihwnaeM
,rehto hcae tsniaga ylbatrofmocnu devohs erew smirgliP
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.em dezingocer eh fi sa eralg htaed a em evag
.orf dna ot meht devaw dna esoon a ekil
.epahs otni kcab enil eht evohs dluow sknom egral owt dna
.tsriht fo deid I erofeb em ni tfel efil fo htrow syad eerht ebyam dah I dna
"!nwod uoy tuc dna uoy dnif ll'ew
ynoga ni denaom eh taht htiW ".yaw
.depmarc selcsum ym dna
.derettum I "?em evigroF"
,manretea mativ ni maut
.rood eht drawot gnikcab dna riahc ym fo tuo gnidils ,derettups I "...yaw
"!mirglip elbmuh a tsuj
.delims raciv ehT ".atlaM
,yrubswerhS ot walc wed s'egroeG .tS detalsnart ohw eno eht er'uoy wonk I"  .nwod knird sih tes raciv ehT
.erauqs eht ssorca pu denil erew smirglip
lepahc desselb eht edistuo thgir morf enots a koot I ,ronoh ym yb ,tuB
,esolC s'raciV eht nwod
stiucsib dna daerb gnivaw
-ratla eht erofeb nellaf d'I emit dnoces eht -llef I
",drofliM ed nhoJ riS dnabsuh ym s'taht dna
".doolb eht htiw ygnits eb t'nod dnA"
",tib a eb ylno
.srehto eht ekil gniklus nwo sih no tis t'ndid
-eman sih saw natsnuD
.gge dedlig eht gniyalpsid ,dnah ym denepo I ".samleahciM
"?knird dna tae nac I oS"
.eson reh pu denrut ehS
.yrellucs denekrad a otni denepo rood ehT
.semit ruof enil taht dnuora tnew I .semit ruoF
.doof eht lla pu rehtag em depleh
.ti morf retaw fo tib a dekcus I
hcruhc enots taerg a
yad eht gnirud evan eht demraw
.yawyna deirt I tub ti ekat ot gniog saw I yaw on saw erehT
# !ti did I  .ti did I
,yrautcnas eht ta dnuora dezag I
.elddup gniknirhs-reve eht pu kaos ot tfel saw
,sriats larips fo tes a pu
"?raciV eht s'erehW"
,mih brutsid ot si eno on dias eH"  .deffuh ehs
",redisnocer ot uoy geb I"
ydrabmoL dna ,yovaS
yelehtarC ta egroeG .tS fo hcruhC hsiraP eht ot kcab
"!ynohtnA .tS ekil mih tpmeT .mih tpmet ,oG
.retaw dicnar ni dekaos cinut ym fo edis tfel eht
,esolC s'raciV eht nwod
,yad lla netae t'ndah I
mih esruc ot em gnirad
.deksa retto eht
.evom ym ekam ot dediced I
.evorp ot tniop a dah I .oN
.edisni detser enots tresed nat fo eceip A
ekam dluoc raciV eht yenom hcum woh tuoba eugnot ym gnitib ,dias I
,dworc a otni kaerb dluow enil eht netfo os yrevE
,esuoh suoegartuo sih dlos eh fi
.ecilahc eht morf knird yam tseirp eht ylno ,yllamroN
",treboR ztiF yrneH riS dna
.renroc a ni pu gnilruc ,dias I
!srotnemrot ym morf em revileD"
.otni nettog dah kcirp sih dna eh stiolpxe gnirad eht fo gnitsaob ruoh duol a ynam tneps eH
,em wohs reven d'eh seicrem rof daelp ot em gnirad
,regnessap ylno eht saw I no neht morF
,llah enots yletats a saw egaraciv ehT
,dnalgnE ni ,yelehtarC ot kcab
.eniw fo tib a htiw neve
thgink xof hsimelF ylrus a
.yawa llup ot gniyrt ,delwoy I "!em dnahnU"
.nun a ron etabilec rehtien saw I
syad ytriht ro ytnewt rehtona rof pihs a fo sdloh gniknits eht edisni bmilc uoy nehT
yawriats larips nedoow tnecifingam a pu
.otni ezeeuqs dluoc I renroc ynit a ylno dah I litnu ograc htiw dellif yllaudarg dah sdloh eht dna
yojne esaelP   .ytiniffaruF no
",thgirla etiuq s'ti ,oN" .delbmum I
"!neppah ti tel flesmiH ythgimlA ehT" .detsetorp I
",ekil uoy fi nac I
,meht ot dellac I ",netsiL"
em erofeb dewob yehT
aes ta syad gnol ytxis retfa
aes yb ereht yaw elohw eht levart dna
meht draeh I .siht dekil
,flow dlo ylkcis a
.yrd nur dah elddup eht ,tsaf ym fo yad hthgie eht yb tuB
.enod naht dias reisaE ".eerf er'uoy
htuom ruoy ni doof fo bmurc a neve hctac ew fi ro yrautcnas eht evael ot yrt uoy fI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
",em ot mih gnirb ,seY" .dereffo eh
?ni emoc esaelp I yaM"  .dias ehs
llawnroC morf nit gniyrrac pihs a fo sdloh gniknits eht edisni bmilc nac uoy
.em rof htap a deraelc dworc ehT
,ynit saw yrauqiler ehT
".thgin lla tog t'nevah ew ,eciohc ruoy ekaM
deppots dah teels eht tsael tA
,sllugaes fo sgniw eht ekil scra dliw ni tpews taht sworbeye yarg dah eH .ksed eht ta tas
redluohs ym revo kcas eht werht I .doof fo lluf kcas yvaeh a htiw os ro teef ytfif klaw enola tel
.revo em dekool dna
,keerG ni noitasrevnoc draeh I
"?emit tsriF"  .deil I
.pohsiB eht nopu ecitsuj dereviled dna reyarp ruoy draeh droL ehT
?uoy t'nod ,no kaolc ruoy tog ev'uoY
.flesmih gnissorc ,delbmum saerdnA "!airaM useI"
,deyalpsid feiht ciler siht ytilimuh elbakramer eht tuoba elbmum
,ciler eniuneg a neve t'nsaw tI"
etuor railimaf emas eht deklaw I
.rood elddim eht no dekconk lrig yrellucs ehT
,retal owt ro ruoh na ssensuoicsnoc deniager I
,cinut tsedom gnol a rof elliam sih deppaws d'eH
tseirp flow a dehcram ni ,retal setuniM ".noS
.sevlehs ot deniahc skoob dna ksed gnitirw a htiw eciffo llams a otni dna
.yad lla feirg em gnivig neeb s'hcamots yM"
.gnorw gnihton enod dah I eveileb ot nageb dna
ti deppid dna refaw noinummoc eht detneserp flow ehT
,thgilrats ees dluoc I dna
.ysatsce fo sraet ni emos
,seirtsepat hcir htiw dehsival dna
.rood eht drawot dereggats I
".emit gnol a gnimoc ti dah ecaf-mutorcs dlO"
".ruoh na ni ezeerf t'now uoy esimorp I
.sresnec egral gnuws ohw sknom reed owt yb dewollof ,syob ratla enilef owt dna
",sevlesmeht stseirp eht morf raeh I nehw ti eveileb ll'I"
,erbmaS otni revoD morf lias s'yad a ekat nac uoy
.etah htiw tohsdoolb seye nworb sih ,dewolleb eh "!ti wenk I !AHA"
.knird eht ekat ot ton egru eht gnithgif ,roolf enots dlo eht fo trap wol a ni elddup a yb despalloc dah I
tekram eht ni ssorc enots dlo eht dnuor
",uoy wohs ll'I ,gnola emoC"
.htgnerts ym fo tsal eht htiw yrc ythgim a evag I
,thgirpu tlob tas I
.deralced raciV eht
.emoR aiv aitsO ro amraP aiv
.teef ykahs no lepahc eht ot kcab degdurt dna
,nialpmoc ot em gnirad
.saes hguor tih ew
;erom yna dnats ylerab dluoc I
.ecaf ym ni rood nedoow tuots eht esolc ot edam ehS   ".uoy neve ton
.sgnul ym fo pot eht ta
.riaper fo deen ni saw ti ,syadawon
.aletsopmoC ed ogaitnaS morf sllehs dna snip mirglip htiw denootsef ,tah ym deppit I
,notsniW ,elbatpeccanu s'tahT
,etag egaraciv dekcolnu eht hguorht tperc I
,lardehtaC s'luaP .tS sdnats
.worbeye na desiar I ".worromot
.zidaC ot su htiw edor ylno sordoweT tuB
yramrifni eht morf knom ehT
.etag eht tuo em dessot dna
?rof tuo kool ot dias retsam ym tac taht er'uoy ,hO"
.elbon dlog a em gnidnah ,yrneH dias
?ereht revo tac niffumagar taht ees uoY"
"!flesmih tsirhC ekil
,lardehtac eht ot kcab gnigdurt erofeb
gniliec ot roolf sciasom dlog dna
.detsetorp I "!oN !oN"
"!ti fo llA .htuom sih morf ti raeh ot tnaw I" .dias I
-?yrneH ti saw -meht fo eno hguoht
,teertS hcruhC eht ot
.sruoh lla ta gnimraws ,ereht erew dlrow eht ssorca morf smirglip
derehtag saw enoyrevE .em was eno oN
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,xiorCaL esoR yb
",uoy nekasrof sah doG"
.yal ecno ti erehw
,erofeb sruoh wef a saw ti naht regnorts tub esraoh tib a llits eciov ym
,toh ylbaraebnu emoceb dah evan eht ni erutarepmet eht ,yad htnet eht yB
,nretnal sih morf eldnac eht koot dna rood kao dlo yvaeh eht dekcolnu yrneH
.sekats llams rof ecid deyalp sdneirf sih elihw etul eht deyalp
.seiks eulb rednu
,moor krad eht otni delbmuts I .ni em gnivohs
".oga shtnom eerht mih rof did yretnesyD" .dias yrneH
noissecorp eht htiw gnola dewollof dah smirglip suoiruc wef a nevE
,em dniheb gnola gnurts smirgliP
hsif fo setib elpuoc a dna
,ratla eht erofeb llef I
"!melasusreJ morf emoh eriuqs sih dna dnabsuh ym thguorb enirhs sih ta reyarp A"
.mahtnarG fo notsniW m'I"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
",denword ylraen eW"
.retawaes yltsom saw taht reeb htiw nwod dehsaw ekah detlas saw netae d'I gniht tsal eht dna
aipoihtE morf tnahcrem aneyh a dna
.doof esufer ot ysae emaceb ti
.delbmur raciV eht
.ecaf sih ni yrauqiler eht gnivaw ,dednamed I
.eseehc fo egdew a no gniwang
snun etabilec fo draeh d'I .kaelb saw tahT ".uoy
:pihs siht no sregnessap rehto ruof erew erehT
ssam eht gnirud drawrof gnilwarC
-dewolla saw I tsom eht
wollaws ot drah emaceb dna ,elihw a retfa eugnot ym ot kcuts srefaw noinummoc ehT
.hcruhc noxaS dlo eht ot yawdim etag eht hguorht
,thgink yllems eht ,dnarreF dna
,won thgir uoy gnah ot su tnaw t'nod uoy fI"
,thgil elttil yrev
.em ot txen meht delip dna si ereht ekac dna tiucsib fo dnik elgnis yreve dna ,eniw fo sksalf
,ecarg s'doG yb ,tuB
",mih ot klat em teL"
.nip kaolc dlo ytsur a yb detcartsid erew smirglip fo sdworc eht dna
.ti evorp ot elcarim a tcepxe I uoy tnes sah droL eht fi ,notsniW"
"?mirglip a rof wartS"
.em revo emac ssenizzid fo evaw A
yad a dna keew a hguorht em nees dah doG
,teertS hcruhC ot tekram eht ni ssorc enots dlo eht dnuor
yaw siht tsael ta tuB
gnippis elbat a ta gnittis
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,aitsO ta tfel dnarreF
saerdnA "!feiht a si tac sihT"
.esuoh eht ot kcab gniyrrucs ,dellac ehs "!tnemom enO"
.elknirw eson ym edam retaw dicnar fo sbut ni dehsaw yltnecer snoops dna slwob fo tnecs ehT
egroeG tniaS desselb eht fo ciler eht etalsnart ot droL eht yb tnes neeb ev'I"
hctip otni denepo tI
,denraw mailliW "!doG tpmet t'noD"
smirglip eht llet dluow saerdnA rehtorB
sutartsorriC tfarcesaB ekil ,slevon reh morf esoR wonk thgim uoY
".esiwrehto uoy ecnivnoc thgim syob enif eseht thguoht I os ,teef dloc teg thgim uoy wenk I"
.dedda thgink eht
faol a fo eceip a ffo gniraet
.hcamots gnilgrug sih gnihctulc ,denaorg eh
,retal setunim wef a swehpen s'raciv eht emac tuO
!nos yhtlaeh a xessE fo ssetnuoC eht gnirb ot yravlaC ot hguone esolc saw ti dna
,anolecraB ni dnal dehcuot teef sih sa noos sa detlob
.egaraciv eht ot enots yradnuob dlo eht morf spoh eerht ni yelehtarC ssorc dluoc uoY
.esnepsus ni sdaeb rieht gnihctulc erew dna
.ssalg nekorb ekil eciov ym
,thgil mid eht otni deppets romra ni sevlow ralucsum owT
.dellac ehs "?ti si ohW"
.gnilwab dna sebor s'tnetinep ym fo meh eht gnissik ,debbos saerdnA
tsiaw sih tuoba eldrig s'thgink a htiw xof a ot txen eulb ni nexiv a dias ",tops yrev siht no luaP .tS desselb eht democlew ohw ronrevog eht
"?thgin ta dedworc siht yllausu ti sI"
.noitidnoc eno no tuB" "...t'nod I"
,raef ym dewollaws I
-yad a ecirht noinummoC .oot kaew saw I
.syad ytrof rof tsoh noinummoc tub gnihton no lepahc siht ni evivrus nac uoy fi ees s'teL
.sehcra enots ni tes srood eerht fo tnorf ni gnidnal worran a ot
",thgin dooG .tser ym deen I
### ".niaga ereh ecaf ruoy wohs reven dna yrubswerhS ot kcab walc dlo ytrid taht ekat ,woN"
,ydrabmoL morf ydnad reed wollaf a ,mirglip enO
,lufdaerd detsat tI
"!retsam ruoy rof tnatropmi yrev gnihtemos evah I"
.yrautcnas eht ot kcab mih ekaT" .dias pohsib eht
.em no saw yramrifni eht ni eye yreve
,naticcO ,euqsaB ,hsilgnE
,tnedicnI anamiV ehT dna
,omrelaP morf dnuobtuO
.dnalecI morf emoh yaw sih no
.atlaM ot og ll'I"
.yrrats dna mraw erew sthgin eht dna
.steknirt dna secips gnilles dna gniyub nioc sih edam eH
,snmuloc tauqs dna sllaw kciht htiw
.tib a gnitsujda seye ym
,tsoH eht tub gnihtyna stae eh fI" .deralced I
"!olluH" ,dellac I niagA
.seldnac gniraeb smirglip fo lluf ,thgiliwt ni won