seye sih erofeb etad eht dehsalf hcihw
,moordeb sih ot revo mih del dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.mrof siht ni hcum yas dluoc eh taht ton
.sdnah elbmin-neht sih neewteb
– nerdlihc denilcni-yllacigolonhcet sih ot noissecnoc a
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ytpo eht detavitca dna sreppils sih ffo dekcik eh
.ecaf sih ssorc elims citehtapmys a gnittel
,yrrow t’noD .ereht ,erehT“
.nellaf yeht dah dab neeb evah dluow tI
thgirb railimaf esoht erew ereht
.ytinav eht no puc a otni deknulp yltew ,serutned sih emac tuO
”?he ,niaga togroF“
.dekcilc kcol eht dna ,desolc rood eht
dediced dah eh erofeb keew eht taht dellacer eh erofeb dessap noitanretsnoc fo tnemom A
.nottub a fo hcuot eht ta ffo deknilb noisivelet ehT
.lla ta krow dluow ti thguoht t’ndah eH
.hcuoc detnecs-eninac eht no teknalb a tuo daerps eh
.snoituacerp gnikat diova ot epyt eht ton saw maS tub
.snoom lluf eht dnuora suoregnad neeb reven dah rehtaf sih
”.thgin etad“ rieht ti llac ,lla retfa ,did yehT
.edis sih no pu delruc dna
,ti tsol t’nevah I sseuG
stseretni tlucco ylddo htiw
.tsaf tuhs saw esuoh eht fo wodniw dna rood yreve erus edam dna
.prahs erom tib a demees sesnes sih rednow oN
.afos ralimis a no nwod ylsselerac flesmih dessot dah eh nehw oga gnol emit a gnillacer
.pu meht kcip ot revo tneb evah llew yrev t’ndluoc eH
.cigam laer htiw derepmat dah
.rood moordeb eht dekcoler eH
.fooh elgnis a htiw draobyek tnaig a no yrots a tuo gniknulp fo tcepsorp eht evarb ot hguone drah sekirts noitaripsni nehw
ffurcs kcen eht yb mih debbarg neht maS
,kcen s’rehtaf sih dnuora mra sih dekooh dna revo dehcaer maS
,tuo tnew thgil ehT
.deneppah dab gnihtemos litnu tiaw naht
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.niaga dekrow ti dnA
,esroH-ehT-odeloT s'eh AD nO .seirellag trAtnaiveD ro ytiniffAruF sih ni
elzzum eninac s’rehtaf sih ffo detlem lwocs eht erofeb gnol t’nsaw ti ,hguone eruS
deciton tsrif d’eh
.su htiw evil emoc yllaer dluohs eH
sdrow egnarts htiw dellif dna
,noom thgirb ylegnarts a fo thgil eht ni sdnuos egnarts gnikaepS
,etihw fo erahs sti naht erom yb dekcelf saw elzzum sih dna ,kcals elttil a tlep eht
,odeloT yb ”yromeM yzzuF“
:rae sih otni ti delknit dna
maS pu delaid eH
,redro ni erutinruf eht tup
meht devom dah eh os
sivaD maS   ---   .ylper eht emac
,desruc eH   !seyE .seyE
.peels rof flesmih ydaer ot nageb sivaD eoJ dna ,tes dah nus ehT
.rehtoM htiw moor sih ni flesmih dekcol tsuj d’eh ,yltsoM
,teknalb sselesu yltsom a sa
noitisop gniyl-flah a ot nwod mih gnillup
,peelsa saw eoJ erofeb gnol t’nsaw tI
,remocwen eht teerg ot revo dekcilf ecaf dna srae sih nehw tub
,draobpuc reppu eht ni snimativ eht rof hcaer ot troffe hcum oot saw ti
”yromeM yzzuF“.yks eht
.dengilaer ti teg ot evah d’eH
.rood eht denepo eh ,yek thgir eht gnidniF
.niaga dnA .niaga dnA
.mp8 tuoba saw tI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
wolg hsiulb tnaillirb eht saw
.nerdlihcdnarg eht dnuora tsael tA
?ti saw yad tahw tuB
suoivbo-os-ho eht s'eh AF no dna
.snoitagilbo namuh laer on dna
reganeet kcurtsnoom a saw eh retfa gnol ,gnol ,gnol litnu niaga dna niaga dna niaga dna niaga dna niaga dnA .niaga dnA
.gnikaos ,knis eht ni dehsiugnal sehsid s’thgin eht fo tsal ehT
,peels ot tnew yllanif eh nehW
,niaga mih ecnivnoc ot yrt ll’I
.taht ,nepo ot reisae hcuM
.ssenxal yldneirf a yb decalper
yzzuF“:yojne esaelP   ".'skob-eht-fo-tuo'
etiuq t’ndluow tI .ecafretni larua eht detsujda eh nehw ffo dehsalf ytpo ehT .esle gnihton ,oN ”?eriuqer uoy esle gnihtyna ereht si ,6502 92 yaM yadrutaS“
,hsur eht ,erusserp eht ,ssenihcti eht
,noitcellocer sih oT
.elcihev a fo noitarepo eht htiw sexelfer sih detsurt regnol on eh ,sediseB
.og ot erehwyna dah eh fi sa t’nsaw ti ,lla retfA
,gniryek sih htiw delbmuf
.ti fo tnemeticxe eht
setirw ohw esroh a si ohw
.teef dewap sih fo ruof lla no pu teg rehtaf sih depleh eh
?aS ,F ,hT ,W ,uT ,M ,uS
mih dniheb esuoh eht ni thgil ylno eht
,eh nehw deneppah tahw sgnilbis sih dna maS ot delaever eoJ taht oga sraey enin dessap rehtoM retfa ylno saw tI
.gnissim erew snimativ sih dnif ot detnioppasid saw eh
nepo depporp yal
.stniop ynam oot ,puY
tenibac detnorf-rorrim eht desolc eoJ
,dehgis maS   .seye wolley
,hcuoc eht otno ylluferac flesmih derewol eh ,moorhtab eht fo tuo gnigdurT
.tros gnivird-fles eht ot desu teg reven dluoc eh dnA
– ytpo eht pu dellac dnammoc derettum A
sreppils sih otni teef sih dekrow ylluferac eh ,eborhtab sih gnihcnic dna hcuoc moor gnivil eht morf gnisiR
.daeh eht no tap a rehtaf sih evag dna delims maS
ssenluftegrof fo mih tcepsus ot tnedurp erom tsuj saw ti dna
,etsaphtoot sih gnivomer retfa
.nehctik eht ot revo delbmahs dna
.syad eseht dah lla yeht seno delgnaf-wen eht ton ,tsael tA
odeloT yb ”yromeM
,mih wenk elpoep wef sa sivaD eoJ tas
,)thguoht eh ,snoituacerp artxe(
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,sraey ni laref yllatot enog t’ndah eoJ
.pu evig d’eh erows eh gnihtemos
.elbisiv sgnaf dna tuo eugnot htiw wollip eht no gniloord
-- tra lausiv sih sa llew sa
.tuoba gniztilb yadakrow eht morf eerf saw eh ,oga sraey lareves deriter gnivaH
.daeh sih gnihctarcs dna
– nruter ni dereffo saw hpmurrah A
.woleb reward eht ot
,derepsihw eh ”,yako s’ti
.ti desu efiw sih nehw dekrow syawla dah dias eoJ ydolem eht gnimmuh
.ereht ni no gniog saw tahw wenk yeht tahw ta derekcins ega fo nerdlihc ehT
.yawa elffuhs trohs a saw moorhtab ehT
.selknirw ynam ooT
.meht tsurt t’ndiD
,hsurbhtoot sih fo seltsirb eht no deraems eh hcihw
,erol lamronarap no hgih reganeet suoutepmi na sa
”.daD ,neht ,erem’C“
.gnirebmuls llits :niaga rehtaf sih no dekcehc eh
deb eht otno pael derobaleb ylthgils a evag eoJ erehw
.won yb tnerehocni yltsom ,mih ot delbmum dna
.muelonil eht ot gnilbmut morf meht detneverp esnopser evixelfer kciuq yllausunu nA
.hsurb sih htiw snoitom ralucric-imes detraeh-flah edam eh elihw egasiv sih detalpmetnoc eH
.enac sih no tas d’eh ekil tlef ti rednow oN
,ytpo sih no krow emos yb dialrevo owt ro wohs a gnihctaw retfA
,noisivelet eht ffo denrut
.rae sih tif
”.deb ot uoy teg s’teL“
,ywenis enog dah selcsum ehT
-- gnitirw sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
daetsni ereh thgin eht gnidneps eb d’eh yas ot emoh gnillaC
,esroH eht odeloT yb
ydob yrruf sih revo eborhtab s’eoJ gnignarraeR
.odnoc s’rehtaf sih kcolnu dluow taht eno eht rof gnihcraes
.hteet sih denimaxe dna ediw denepo eh ,htuom sih gnisnir dna tserC eht fo redniamer eht tuo gnittipS
,knis eht ni sehsid eht dehsinif eh sa thguoht maS
.tif etiuq t’ndah serutned sih rednow oN
,esion dnuorgkcab emos rof noisivelet eht no gnippilF
.hguone railimaf erew noitanretsnoc ni dessorc smra eht hguoht
.keew tsap eht ni naht yadot yhca erom erew sregnif dna stnioj sih rednow oN
slobmys egnarts htiw detaroced koob elttil A
.yltnetop dnA .did ti tuB
.derit oot - seye siH
,hcuoc eht morf pu gnidnatS
”,daD ,ydaerla yaw ym nO“
,selcsum sih fo tuo noisnet eht dna
,draobpuc eht no bonk eht llup dna psarg ot gniniarts retfA
.rehtaf sih yb tas dna
hcuoc eht ot revo edorts maS
morf ni gnimaerts
.thgin noom lluf a no s’rehtaf sih ot etuor ne flesmih dnuof d’eh raey siht emit driht eht saw sihT
,thgil s’noisivelet eht fo olah nayc eht ni ,erehT
si yrots s’yadot dna
,ygrene fo egrus eht
.gninrom eht ni slaeppa rieht sserdda dluow eH
.delbmurg dna tas tsuj eh ,hguoht ,woN
,netfo erom dna erom gnittegrof saw ,traeh sih sselb ,daD
.eno yb eno yb eno sllip eht denwod eh ,rood rotaregirfer eht morf retaw fo ssalg a gnihcteF .thguoht eh
.won hguone dlo era sdik ehT
.hteet gniniamer sih no krow ot tes dna
.retnuoc eht no tuo sllip eht gnillips ,reniatnoc aS eht nepo deirp eH