tcepsa lacisyhp eht sa hcum sa tsael ta taht deyojne eh dnuof eppillihP dna ,ti ta doog yrev saw ehS
.pmur sih ezeeuqs ot nwod kcab dils wap reH ".epoh I ,uoY"
.lavorppa fo elbmur tfos a tuo tel dna liat sih gaw tub pleh t'ndluoc eppillihP
.ot dah yltcirts ehs naht erom tib a etiuq did ehs thguoht eh hcihw
,tnet rennid eht morf seidob dna doof delgnim eht fo dellems ruf reh dna ,esolc yltnasaelp saw ehS .ylthgil ereht gnitser dna spih reh gnidnif swap nwo sih ,tib a deggurhs eH "?uoy od
,yllairotaripsnoc ni denael ehS ".stib
,gnorw tuo talf semitemos dna ,ylluflliks ssel dels eht ot detcaer yeht yaw eht rof etasnepmoc ot gnivah ,mih no krow erom tol a saw tahT
,detnap ehs ",redraH"
.ti detaicerppa eppillihP
.niaga dehgis eppillihP
.taorht s'revol derruf-etihw sih otni gnitnap
.elpuoc a era miT dna selrahC ,llew hO" "?tsoM"
.repeed tnih a pils mih gnikam
.spih reh no gnitser swap reh dna reh dniheb gniggaw liat reh
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab gnikcilf srae sih
.dels eht gnidir rof leef eht teg ot gnol reh ekat t'ndid ti dna ,renetsil prahs a saw alebaS
.meht hguorht tnes stnemevom rieht stloj neddus eht ta dehctiwt meht fo htob dna ,tnemevom hcae htiw xes s'alebaS ta deggut tonk s'eppillihP .skaep rieht morf nwod emac yeht sa gnitnap ,emit emos rof rehtegot yal sgod owt ehT
.egnellahc a rof pu s'maet ,enif s'taht tuB
.sredir dels fo tsil eht dna eludehcs omed s'yad eht rof esruoc eht tuoba lahsram eht htiw gniklat dehsinif tsuj dah eH
.dels eht ot denrut dna dekniw ehS ".won roF
.rehtie ,wons eht ni tuo gnikrow sgod dels dalc-yllaminim fo hcnub a gnihctaw dnim t'ndid yllausu somed ta ecneidua eht ,ecneirepxe s'eppillihP nI .liart eht no tuo erew yeht erofeb dloc gnitteg morf meht tpek ti ,ni staoc retniw rieht htiW
.emac eh litnu skcub prahs ,trohs wef a hguorht gnivom spih sih tsuj ,gnisnet ydob eritne sih
.dekrep ,dehctiwt srae reh dna dehsalf seye s'alebaS
.yleritne tuo meht gnivael ton elihw ,rehto hcae htiw tahc ot ytinutroppo erom evah alebaS dna eppillihP tel ot troffe suoicsnoc a gnikam eb ot demees yehT
.yldetniop spih sih dekcub eH ".epoh
,htooms eht ,reh edisni gnihctiwt llits htgnel
"?seno rehto emos wonk uoY ?haey hO"
srats eht neewteb
,sih ot ylmrif erom meht gnisserp ,spih reh dehcra ehS ".doog
.ruf kciht sih hguorht gnicart swalc tnulb ,kcab sih gnola dna kcen sih nwod wap a deliart ehS ".haeY"
.ecar-dim yllausu toN .semitemoS"
.denilcer ehs sa mih rof moor gnikam ,deb eht no kcab detfihs neht ,deb reh no tas dna kcab spets elpuoc a koot ehS ".dooG
.daeh reh koohs dna kcab nirg nwo reh tohs ehS
"?trats I od erehw ,hu oS"
,dewols stnemevom reh tub ,meht neewteb wap reh tpek ehS
.tsurht eh sa gnilbbin ,taorht reh fo ruf eht ni elzzum sih deirub eH
.revo deklaw dna enil gut reh dekoohnu enaJ
.rae sih debbur rehto reh elihw ,kcab sih gnola ylthgil wap a nar alebaS ".oot
.daeh sih dekcoc dna desuap eppillihP
yrots s’yadoT dna
,tlep reh rednu ssentfos tnasaelp eht dna ylleb reh fo ruf eht hguorht wap a gninnur dna reh ot txen pu gnilwarc ,ecnatsid eht desolc dna detrons eH
.sloots dna sesac tnemurtsni fo elbmuj a saw yrehpirep eht dnuora aera ehT
.nihc sih dekcil dna mih ta pu delims alebaS
.esrap etiuq t'ndluoc eh kool a mih evag ehS
.mhtyhr ksirb a ot pu flesmih gnikrow ,retsaf elttil a ,niaga ti did eH .elttil a deredduhs ehS
.niaga tlih eht ot pu kcab neht dna kcab gnippils kcoc sih ,spih sih dellor dna reh dessik eH
.mih retfa elttil a tsuj esaeler nwo reh dnuof ehs sa deb eht otni kcab elzzum reh deppit ehs dna ,reh edisni emac eh sa ydob sih ot pu flesreh llup ot demees ehS
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.nihc sih dekcil dna mih ta dennirg ehS ".os hcum yreV"
,owt rof elbatrofmoc dekool taht deb a desuoh ti tub ,egral ylbirret t'nsaw tI
"?enaJ dna uoy ,ekil oS"
.epoh I ,thgin lla sgod repip etuc ,yad lla someD"
.xes s'tI" .dias neht
.trapa eb ot raeb t'ndluoc yeht taht spahrep ro
".taht ot pu krow I yllausU ?tonk eht htiW"
".nalp a ekil sdnuoS"
.kool lacitpeks ylesnetni na reh evag dna ,htaerb a koot ,deppots eH
.ylevitaicerppa revo reh dekool eH ".nac
?maet a ni xeS" "?nommoc taht sI"
,tnemetats txen reh delworg yllacitcarp ehS ".ebyam thgin worromoT"
.ti morf pils ot gnitrats saw kcoc sih yaw eht ro htaehs sih fo gnillews eht edih ot gnihton did htolcniol siH
,kcen reh ni elzzum sih deirub eppillihP dna
"?ebyam ,wohs a fo tib a no tup ot tnaw uoy fi oS"
klaw a rof pu tem yeht neht dna
.depsag ehs dna denethgit ffurcs sih no pirg reh neht dna ,meht neewteb pils wap a tlef eH
.nommoc ytterp hO
,noitartsnomed eht ni gnitapicitrap dna gnidnetta sklof eht roF
.sdrawretfa gnimaeb saw ti did ohw enoyreve dna gnignellahc oot t'nsaw liart eht tub
.denialpmoc eh taht toN
.pu tes etius fo tros a evah I dna dnab yM" .deddon ehS
"?hcum oot gnirahs eb t'now ew dna
.liat sih gniggaw ,reh ta delims eH ".noitarud
woh repip a wohs ,yas ,ot eerf er'uoy oS"
.kniht I ,thginot gnivig tuB" .ylthgil spih sih dekcub eH "!htoB"
.mrof edun-ylraen reh derimda eh sa meht gniodnu dna htolcniol sih fo seit eht gnidnif swap sih ,elzzum sih fo tuo dellol eugnot s'eppillihP "?mm ,sruoy
,,irauR nosmirC yb ”delS naicilaG“
.reh ta nwod nirg dluoc eh os swap sih no pu flesmih dehsup eh ",oS"
".uoy no kool doog a s'tI"
.smoor etavirp yna evah t'ndid yeht ,neht tub ,s'maet sih ot derapmoc llams saw aera nommoc s'tnet ehT .ni reh dewollof eh sa devresbo ehs ",tneinevnoc s'taht ,hO" .deilper ydoboN
.rennam diugnal ylralimis a ni gnivom
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.lworg elttil a tuo tel ehS ".yltsom
.alebaS ot denrut ehS ".egnellahc
?thgin ta mraw peek uoy od woh ,em llet esaelP !t'nod I erus m'I"
,hhhhhhhhoO" .esaeler sih htiw rae reh otni denaom eh dna ,reh edisni dekrej dna debborht kcoc siH
.ffurcs sih gnola bur ot kcab dehcaer dna tnemesuma fo krab tfos a tuo tel ehS
.ylteiuq gnilworg dna ruf etihw reh hguorht gnilbbin
.tloj drah a fo daetsni gnileef mraw
eppillihP .sdrow reh ot ycnegru gnidda ,htgnel sih dnuora xes reh dehcnelc ehS
.lacinhcet erom tib a eb d'ti ,saw ti fi neve dna ,deraperp ton s'liarT
.maet eht htiw kcehc em tel
,tuo psag dna spil reh ta kcil ot elzzum sih derewol eH
eppillihP ".sthgin dloc no mraw peek sgod dels naidanaC uoy woh em wohs ot uoy gnitcepxe era setammaet ruoy noisserpmi eht teg I .oS"
,kcab reh rednu smraerof sih deppils dna swoble sih ot flesmih derewol eH
.liat sih deggaw eH "?thginoT"
,sliart dekcap-llew esiwrehto revo
.sredluohs reh pirg ot swap sih gnilruc
.tniop eht dessim d'eh esac ni ,spih reh dekcub ehS ".stnuoc ti erehw hturt eht sllet ti kniht I ,onnud I ,mmM" .keehc sih dekcil tub ,niaga detrons ehS ".hgU .emankcin tahT"
.dennirg dna ylkciuq flesreh derevocer tub ,kcab srae reh dekcilf alebaS ".spih sih wollof dna kcab hsup tsuj ,wonk'Y"
.rettug eht fo tuo dnim ruoy peek won yeH"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.gnidnats fo gnikniht saw I"
,sisab raluger a no selcsum reh desu ehs ekil ,dilos tsuj ,tfos ro niht ro yriw ro ykcots ton
,krow ot tneg siht tup s'teL"
.tsiaw reh ta cirbaf fo tonk a ot tnorf reh revo meht dediug dna swap sih dnuof ehS
.sreyal erew ereht dna ,did yllausu eh naht sehtolc erom tol elohw a gniraew saw ehS
.yawa reh evag reh dniheb deggaw liat reh yaw eht tub ,psag kcom a evag ehS ".xes
".thginot flesym ot lla uoy tnaw I" .detrons ehS
.ti demrifnoc ehs nehw ,wap ni wap ,rennid retfa edistuo klaw a gnikat erew yehT
.mih ta yllufyalp delworg ehS "?sehctib repip rehto yna rof kool t'ndluoc uoy os emit ruoy deziloponom I fi tahw dnA"
.redluohs reh revo krims a alebaS dna eppillihP tohs alleH
,tnemesuma detrons dna erusopmoc reh tsol ehs ereh dna ",D giB ,no emoC"
"?rof og uoy od gnol woH"
.desolc tekcaj reh peek ot demees taht selggot fo seires a ot mih dediug alebaS ".ym hO"
,hsul a mih gnivig noitom wols
"!eppillihP ,em eiT !kcuF"
.wohs ot tfel hcum dah d'eh ekil t'nsaw ti ,esruoc fO
.tsehc sih fo pot eht revo ylthgil meht nur ot sih fo tuo sregnif reh deppils neht dna swap sih yb esolc flesreh dellup ehS ".t'ndid
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna eseht piks nac uoy
.hcnul rof kaerb trohs a ylno htiw ,yad lla ylraen nar dna ,thgie dnuora tuo sredir tsrif rieht gnikat ,ylrae yad eht detrats d'yehT
.kcab tohs alebaS "?stnap ruoy otni nevE"
.nwod dekool dna sreh edisgnola elzzum sih dekcut eH ".ereh tratS"
,liart eht no tuo er'uoy nehw ,oS"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sih tsniaga spih reh dellup dna ylteiuq delworg eH
.rehtona eno fo tuo dna ni dewolf snoitasrevnoc eht yaw eht gniyojne eb ot demees ,trap reh rof ,alebaS
"?edir ot tnaw uoy od woH
.yltsom ,haeY" .dehguoc eH
.ojod eht ro ,pohs eht
.enil eht no sgod fo riap hcae htiw ecnerefnoc trohs a gnivah ,maet eht fo tnorf eht ot kcab yaw reh edam ehs ,taht htiW ".dels
"?ecalp ruoy tuoba tahw...oS"
.niorg sih otni kcab neht dna wap sih otni drawrof gnisserp ,spih reh dellor ehS
.tnet s'maet sih fo noitcerid eht ni yleugav devaw dna dennirg eH ".hguoht
.t'ndid uoy erus m'I"
"!ees ll'ew taht retfA"
"?uoy evah ,tey eman eht ta dekool t'nevah uoY" .detrons ehS ".gnola
”delS naicilaG“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.ylleb eht ni mih dekop ehs dna ,dehguoc eppillihP ".pu
irauR nosmirC yb
.sllems elbatrofmoc dna mraw
"?nur regnol a rof pu syug uoY"
.skrab evitamriffa fo surohc a saw erehT
uoy rof daer dna nettirw ,”delS naicilaG“
.naom a tuo tel ehs dna rethgit delruc ffurcs sih no pirg reH
?deksa ehs ",gnimoC"
.tfahs sih fo pit desopxe eht revo spitregnif deddap-rehtael ,tfos reh gniliart ,rehgih neht ,htaehs sih revo ti dehsurb dna wap a tuo dehcaer ehS ".god
,nehctik eht ni dnuof eb netfo nac eh ,gnitirw ton nehW
,I" .won kool taht gnisrap fo tnih a dah eH
.ruf reh fo etihw krats eht htiw tsartnoc eht gnirimda ,cirbaf krad eht revo sregnif sih gniyalps ,dnuom reh revo wap sih nar eppillihP ,seitnap reh ot nwod saw ehs nehW
.kcen sih fo kcab eht revo ylwols gnittep otni delttes dna ffurcs sih no pirg reh dexaler ehS
.secar gnirud taht naht redrah nar yeht dna ,nuf erew somed -- dnim t'ndid maet ehT
.ecalp reh ot kcab mih nekat ro
.gnicar detrats yeht erofeb gniog smsilobatem rieht teg maet eht depleh tuokrow eht dna ,selcsum rieht rof doog saw tI
.stnemevom sih gnidaer no alebaS dna dels eht gnivird no desucof eppillihP elihw ,liart railimafnu gnikaerb fo ssenisub suoires eht ot yltrams gnihctiws maet eht
".ruoh na flah stsal yllausu nur ruO .rre
.krow nimda yad-tneve eht fo tser eht htiw gnola ,mih ot llef yllacipyt taht ,revird sA
.tnaw yeht fi su fo lluf tnet elohw a s'ereht lleW"
.pam eht no pool regnol a was I thguoht I ?gnippiks neeb ev'ew krof a ereht t'nsaW .rrre ,I"
.srae sih fo eno fo esab eht bur ot kcen sih fo kcab eht pu gnippils ,ruf sih hguorht deliart sregnif reH .deddon ehS
.eltbus taht t'nsaw maet eht -- ti fo erawa yltcefrep saw ehs taht detcepsus eppillihP
"?od ot evah I od tahw ,oS"
.deksa ehs "?ecnerefnoc eht fo tser eht gniod uoy era tahW"
.kcab deppiuq ehs "?gniviecer ro gniviG"
.eb dluow rewsna sih tahw fo aedi doog a dah ehs noisserpmi eht tog eppillihP .sregnif reh neewteb rae sih fo pit eht debbur ehS
"!aedi on dah I !ssendooG"
"?taht sredir ruoy lla llet uoY ?os taht si ,hO"
".ti tuoba lamrof yrev t'nera su fo tsoM !semitemoS" .dennirg eH
,noisserpxe reh morf dna ,denot rehtar ,sgod dels tsom ekil ,saw eh wenk eppillihP ,trap sih roF .ti od ot myg a ot og t'ndid tub
.llew sa ,tnetnoc ylriaf eb ot demees ehs os ,emit ot emit morf sih otni depmub liat s'alebaS
-- dilos dekool ehS
.noitarud eht rof edoba elbmuh yM"
-- dennirg eppillihP ".em kcuf"
,irauR nosmirC yb
,mmm ,fo tol a evah eW
.ti no tnemmoc t'ndid ehs ,deciton alebaS fi tub ,srae dekrep-yllufyalp dna krims a yb deinapmocca yllausu ,laem eht gnirud tniop emos ta eppillihP htiw tcatnoc eye lufgninaem ekam ot yrassecen ti leef ot demees maet eht fo rebmem rehto rehto yrevE
,dluoc eh sa tsaf dna drah sa tsurht ot egarevel eht desu god ehT
.did eh taoc elbuod eht evah t'ndid ehs tub ,sih sa htgnel emas eht tuoba saw ruf reH
.gniggir eht fo tser eht dna dels eht pu tes ot eppillihP gnivael ,maet eht fo tser eht denioj dna dels eht ni tik eht morf sessenrah eht koot miT dna selrahC ,enod krow yvaeh ehT
.tca eht pu gnivig yllanif ,detrons ehS
reh otni depmub eh nehw tlef ti doog woh tsuj dna derevoc htolc niol sih elttil woh tsuj fo erawa yrev saw eppillihP dna ,rehto hcae otni eltsoj d'yeht ,pmub a deraelc ro renroc a denrut yeht nehW
.meht ta derutseg eH
,deredduhs dna delworg eppillihP
.deklaw ehs nehw pmur reh revo deyaws liat reh yaw eht yllaicepsE
,liart etanretla eht tih yeht ecnO
.eb thgim uoy kniht I ,mraw erehwemos er'ew taht won
;mih dniheb ylwols deyaws liat s'eppillihP "?mmM" .nageb ehs "...oS"
.ti gnillif etiuq ton ,wap sih ni tlef ti yaw eht gniyojne ,stsaerb reh fo eno puc ot pu neht
gnivil a rof erawtfos setirw nosmirC
.tsaf dna drah spih sih gnikcub ,emit on detsaw
.deddon ehS "?uoy ti sI .haN"
,tsap deppils ti sa epacsdnal eht gnivresbo emit eht dessap yltsom alebaS dna eppillihP
.gnihcterts dna oidrac pumraw emos hguorht maet eht fo tser eht del enaJ dna alleH elihw gniggir eht tuo gniyal detrats dna omed rieht rof etuhc gnitrats tfihsekam eht otni dels eht deluah
,rrrE" "?regnol rof og uoy naC"
.suolucidir saw yllaer ti
,mih fo tnorf ni neddir dah alebaS erofeb neve ,pu degrahc ytnelp mih tfel dah snur s'yad ehT
,daeh reh koohs ehS ".wonk
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
.moor txen eht otni reh dewollof dna lavorppa sih delworg eH ".ekam
"?regnol yob ruo edir ot gnikool ,oh-
,mih ta gninnirg ,denrut dna eppillihP morf yawa pets a koot hctib derruf-etihw ehT ".desserdrevo
.noisserpxe reh otni pils ot detrats krims a tub
"?taht ekil d'uoy dnA" "!yrev hO"
.nihc sih deppin ehS
.reh erofeb edun doots eh dna yawa llef htolc sih nehw
.moor eht ta derutseg dna mih ecaf ot denrut ehS
.wonk uoy kniht I"
.doog leef uoy ,kcuf hO"
.su fo lla rof si ti woh tsuj s'taht tub ,ot pu er'ew tahw wonk ylbaborp ll'yeht ,lleW" .deggurhs ehS
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
.niaga reh dessik dna nwod dennirg eppillihP ".ssendooG"
.htob meht ta dekrims enaJ ".seno etuc eht tsuJ"
.dettur eh sa gnitnap dna gnilworg saw ehS
.dehguoc eppillihP dna ,dekrims alebaS
.moor letoh llams a ekil rehtar ,egaggul fo seceip elpuoc a dna ,sesac tnemurtsni erom elpuoc a
.reh deit eh nehw ylthgit spih sih deppirg sgel reh dna ,meht neewteb retsaf gnivom saw wap s'alebaS "!kcuf
,maet eht sdrawot detcejorp dna eciov sih desiar eH ".maet
.ti fo kniht ot emoc ,devom pmur reh woh dnA
hO" .nirg a htiw alebaS ta deddon ehS
.gnola gnimoc uoy htiw ko er'yeht fi ees dna kcehc em tel ,nur tsal ruo rof gnipperp er'ew ,llew hO"
.edis raf eht ta sniatruc fo tes a sdrawot mih del dna wap sih no deggut ehs nehT "!esruoc fO"
.desserdrevo llits er'ew tub ,seY"
.nwod dna pu mih kool dluoc ehs os kcab pets trohs a koot ehS ".su
,wonk uoY" .dennirg eppillihP ".desserd-revo leef ot gnitrats m'I ,wonk uoY"
.yb deppils ti erofeb erutaef niarret ro erutcurts gnitseretni na ro weiv ecin a tuo gnitniop
.mih otni kcab gnisserp ,delkcuhc ehS ".kniht
.ylfeirb desnet tsaerb reh no wap sih dna ,hcuot reh ta gnitnap flesmih dnuof eppillihP "?sey
,mmM" ".aera gnipeels nwo ym evah I
,dehguoc dna trohs deppots
.pu gnidnats ti ekat ll'I sseug I ...hu oS"
.liart eht no dnim ruoy deen I !nuf hcum oot evah t'noD"
.tsiaw reh morf llef cirbaf fo hsas a dna tonk eht didnu eh sa ylteiuq delworg eH ".egaggul
wons yredwop ,thgil fo sehcni elpuoc a tsuj meht gnivig ,thginrevo llafwons thgil a dah d'yeht -- rehtaew tcefrep ti htiw thguorb gninrom ehT
.D giB ,uoy ekil thgim I kniht I ,wonk uoY"
.yaw emas eht tlef ehs demees ti dna ,sehtolc reh fo tuo reh teg ot tiaw t'ndluoc eH
.dnim ot emac esle revetahw dna ,rehtaew eht ,liart eht tuoba rehto hcae htiw gnittahc ,ecaps emos meht evag sgod rehto eht tub ,rennid ta maet eht htiw tas alebaS dna eppillihP
.ruf sih ni sworruf gnivael ,kcab sih pu ylthgil swalc reh deggard ehS ".deciton I"
.hcum oot mih gnitcirtser ton tub egarevel emos flesreh gnivig ,spih sih dnuora ylthgil parw ot sgel reh detfil dna wap eerf reh ni steehs reh deppirg ehS ".uoy od oS"
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
.tib a dekcilf srae siH "...tnet eno otni elip tsuj adnik ew ,mraw peek ew woh fo gnikaepS .llew ,hhU"
.htolcniol sih tsniaga desserp pmur reh os pu dekcab neht ,mih morf yawa denrut ehS
.rae reh ni derumrum eh ",hctam tuoba tsuj ew woN"
"?gnidnats ro teksab eht ni gnidir uoY"
.eb naC" ".nuf sdnuoS"
"?sgod dels ynroh ,dekan fo elip gib a tsuj s'ti os
.nur ruo elbuod tuoba dluoc ew ,yltcerroc llacer I fI .haeY"
"?ffo su ees ot emoC !ereht yeH" .reh ta dennirg eppillihP .pu deklaw alebaS nehw yad eht fo nur tsal rieht rof gnipperp erew yehT
.yllacitsaisuhtne deddon eH "?mraw yats uoy
.nac ylniatrec uoY"
.hguoht ,gninrom eht ni suolaej elttil a eb thgim yeht ,mmM"
.daeh sih koohs eH
.egaggul ym ni s'tahw wonk t'nod uoy ,hO"
.daeh reh koohs alebaS
"!regnuoy yna gnitteg ton s'thgin ,neht no emoC"
"?taht htiw uoy pleh I naC"
.mhmM" .deddon alebaS "!yzoC .ecin yreV"
.tnemtnetnoc ni hsawa yltneg gnileef mih dah ynapmoc s'alebaS ,esruoc fo dna ,laem doog a ,dels eht no yad doog a
!draoba emoclew ,neht lleW !hO"
.sih edisni tsuj ,rab eht no swap reh htiw ,srennur eht no mih fo tnorf ni doots ehS
.mmmmM" .seitnap reh kcuhs ot nwod tneb dna dennirg alebaS
,miT dna selrahC ,sgod leehw owt eht dna eppillihP
.etavirp tib a dnA
".no gniog gnihtemos evah smaet tsoM .rehtegot emit fo tol a dneps dna ygrene
41 taeH ni seirots trohs sah eH
.deddon ehS "?tnet maJ"
.keehc reh ta dekcil dna sredluohs s'alebaS no pirg sih dexaler eppillihP
.redluohs sih deppals dna liat reh deggaw enaJ ".pam
.ylthgil taorht reh deppin eH ".rerettalF"
,ecnelis otni llef yeht
"?yaw eht fo tros tsuj s'tI" .deggurhs eH ".rehtie
.nuf rof seirots dna
.eppillihP htiw srennur eht no dnats dluow seno suorutnevda erom eht fo wef a tub ,eciohc ysae na saw hcihw ,teksab eht ni tas sredir tsoM
.stib ygdod eht otni teg ew nehw ereh dael s'D giB wollof ot erus artxe eb neht ,lleW" .deddon enaJ ".gnidnats
.sivlep reh otni ylmrif gnisserp saw htaehs sih tnaem taht dna ,thgieh ralimis fo erew yehT
.ruf eht hguorht gnippils sregnif
.wons hguorht dels eht fo ssih eht dna ylteiuq gninnur sgod wollef sih fo dnuos eht tub gnihton htiw dels eht no eb ot ekil saw ti tahw meht wohs dna tuo sklof ekat ot gnitteg
.detcepxe eb ot rehtar saw ,detcelfer eh ,hcihw ,t'ndid eh sevruc dah osla ehS
.taeh reh ni detlih saw eh litnu drawrof desserp eh sa nwo sih fo eno tuo tel eppillihP
,kcen sih revo hsurb ylthgil ot pu wap a nar ehS ".ecar-
.esnopser ni ti dexelf eH
,deyalp repip naicilaG eht alebaS elihw decnad god-dels eht epillihP ,emit tsaL
.drawrof spih sih desae eh sa flesmih gnidiug ,htgnel sih dnuora rehto sih depparw dna reh ot txen wap a decarb eH .mih ta pu ylitsul delworg ehs dna ,niaga kcen sih dnuof wap s'alebaS
,rehtegot nward erew yeht hguoht sa ,yllufecrof deniojer neht ,llaf stnemrag eht tel ot detrap spih rieht elihw eht lla dna ,roolf eht ot elddup a ni llef triks reh neht dna ,ti denioj trihs reh dna ,roolf eht ot llef tekcaj reH
.sehtolc reh fo sroloc mraw ,dexim eht htiw detsartnoc ruf etihw reh woh dna devom ehs yaw eht gnirimda ,reh retfa dettort dna dennirg eppillihP
.tnet reh sdrawot mih deggut dna niaga wap sih koot alebaS ".tnaw
"?thgin eht fo tser eht gniod uoy era tahW"
em wohs ll'uoy fi enim uoy wohs ll'I"
".tfel syad wef a llits s'ereht tub ,tey toN"
.reh edisni mih gniyt ,kcuts ti erofeb semit wef a ecnartne reh ta gnihctac ,yldipar dellews tonk siH
"?ffuts toh ,sruoy ro ecalp ym...oS"
.emit dneps ot syaw retteb ynam yrev fo kniht t'ndluoc eH
hU" .seye sih gnillor ,dehgis neht ,htaerb peed a koot eppillihP "?eriF
,snoitartsnomed gniddels fo strap etirovaf s'eppillihP fo eno saw tI
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht eht saw sihT
,sreh otni ylwols spih sih dnuorg eH
.dels eht pots annog ton m'I ,rehto hcae tcartsid owt uoy esuac' revo seog gniht eht fI
.noisserpxe tneconni na htiw mih ta daeh reh dekcoc dna ,sih gnipsalc llits wap reh ,mih fo tnorf ni dnats ot pets a koot ehS "...rrre ,hhha hO"
.mih tsniaga desserp reh gnivah fo
,niaga dennirg eH
".ti diova nac I fi stnap raew t'nod I"
.sgel reh dexelf ehs sa deb eht ffo pu gnisir spih reh ,mih otni pu gnisserp ,denaom dna kcab reh dehcra ehs esuaceb ,taht yojne ot demees ehS
.enil wot eht no sgod eht sa hcum sa etiuq ton tub ,tuokrow a fo ytnelp tog llits eh ,revird eht sA
was ehs tahw htiw detnioppasid ton saw ehs derugif eh
.esiwrehto ro larutan ,erew staoc rieht doog woh no desab yrav ylbaborp dluow ecneirepxe rieht
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer eb lliw hcihw
".em edisni uoy tnaw I thginoT"
.haeY" .deddon ehS "?haeY"
.sehtolc reh hguorht edis reh fo evruc eht gnicart ,pu wap a dils eH ".eb
.pmur reh otni dnuorg dna sreh otni ylmrif swap sih desserp eh dna ,esnopser ni lworg nwo sih reffo ylno dluoc epilihP
,mmM" .lufthguoht gnikool ,desuap neht ,emit siht nihc sih deppin ehS
.rae reh delzzun dna nwod kcab flesmih derewol neht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dnatsrednu t'ndid eh egaugnal a ni tuo gnillac ,tnet eht otni dekcud ehs erehw ,noitanitsed rieht ot gard trohs a saw tI
,dezeeuqs dna sih ni wap rehto reh koot eH ".eruS .huh-
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.pih reh no wap a detser eH ".eb
".edir ot ereh m'I !yldraH"
.gnizeerf woleb-llew ylpsirc saw erutarepmet eht dna ,raelc saw yks eht
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna 1 WALC dna
:yojne esaelP  .wons dna
.flesmih ,no rekaerbdniw a dah eppillihP
.shgiht reh neewteb gnileenk saw eh litnu sgel delffuhs ,ssendrawkwa elbadiovanu fo tib a htiw ,dna detfihs eH
.retteb hcum neeb evah t'ndluoc ti ,maet eht fo tser eht dna eppillihP roF
.mih dnuora kcils dna toh erew sllaw reh ,edisni flesmih desae eh sa dna gnimoclew dna mraw dna yffup erew sdlof reH
.dlrow eht fo tser eht fo hcum os morf ecap fo egnahc a hcus saw tI
.oot ,doog ytterp eb d'tahT"
.ekam ot cisum nwo ruo evah eW ?mmm ,ebyam ,retal tuB"
"?kniht uoy od ,taht yb naem yeht dluoc revetahW"
,mih otni kcab desserp ehs ro
.god ,htob em dna uoY" .detrons dna hcuot sih otni pu kcab reh dehcra alebaS ".kniht I ,nooS"
,tnemmoc eht ta denaorg eppillihP ".D
,spih rieht fo noinuer hcae yltfos denaom dna kcab reh dehcra alebaS
".erehwyreve uoy teg ll'tI"
.hcum oot ti tuoba kniht ot gnideen ton dna liart eht htiw railimaf ,nar yeht sa dettahc maet ehT
.xes tuoba gniklat er'yehT
.yllufepoh liat sih deggaw eH
.rehtie ,rehto hcae ot evisulcxe t'nera yeht tuB
.flesreh neht ,mih ta dekool dna kcab deppets god etihw ehT ".retteb s'tahT"
.ecnartne s'ecaps eht revo cirbaf fo reyal dnoces a llup ot mih tsap dehcaer ehS ".etavirp
"?ta gnikool ahctahW .haey hO"