.repeed gnihtemos dna murd erans a yb yltrohs denioj
lleh hO" .gnihsalf seye reh ,ylediw dennirg dna kcab denael
fo strap owt fo ts1 eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
ecnis ,maet eht no sgod tsellams eht eno ,hcus sa dna ,revird eht saw eppillihP .detrons eH
.ydob sih tsniaga doog oot yleritne tlef ehS .reh dnuora smra sih depparw dna delkcuhc eH
,deyalp ehs sa segnahc reh gniwollof ,roolf ecnad llams eht dnuora mih dael reh gnittel ,ecap tpek eH
.wap eerf reh htiw devaw neht dna sredluohs reh revo pu rehgih lwahs reh dellup alebaS
.retteb eht ,gnihtolc ssel eht os ,toh ytterp nur ew dna ,god dels a m'I ,lllleeeW" ".meht fo hcum os ylerar tub ,snaidanaC nees evah I"
"?deb ot og tsuj ro ,ti tuoba gnihtemos od ot tnaw uoy diD" .dennirg ehS ".ereht
.gninrom eht ni enif syawla s'ehs tub ,I od rehtieN" .deggurhs alleH ".ti
,hcuot ecin a eb d'tahT
.evol ni s'ydobemos kniht I"
,”delS naicilaG“   :yojne esaelP
.ti ssim ot emahs a eB .tneve eht fo emos gniees dna ecitcarp rof si worromoT
.ecnelis eht ni detrons eh dna ,noitnetta gniyap neeb t'ndah eh elihw pu dekcap dna cisum rieht deppots dah snaicisum ehT
.dedworc saw tnet gnirehtag ehT
.taert yM ?rennid teg ot eraC .haeY" .dennirg eH
.segnellahc reh gniteem
,sepip fo liaw dehctip-hgih eht htiw dellif saw tnet eht neht dna ,lwoh prahs
.stiw sih gnirevocer dna gniknilb ,ereht doots
"?niaga no og uoy od nehW"
"?meht eldnah nac uoy knihT"
.pu peek ot nrettap otaccats a tuo gnipmots ,gnidniwnu ,gnippots dna gninnips flesmih dnuof eppillihP
.ni mih devaw dna tap a pmur sih evag ehS ".gninrom
.sey ,srats emos ees I ,hhhA"
.rerettalF" .wap eerf reh htiw pih eht ni mih degdun dna detrons ehS ".siht
!doog er'uoY .ti nees ev'ew ,gnicnad evol uoY .no emoc hO" .detrons ehS
.sknird rieht htiw hcneb nedoow gnol a fo dne eno gnola ni dworc ot selbat rehto tsap yaw rieht deltsoj seiksuh fo puorg ehT
.deddon ehS ".sey hO" "?esohT"
ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
"?omed ruoy si gnol woH"
.sreeb erom wef a retfa tnet eht ta kcab pu kooh ot gninnalp yletinifed era su fo wef a ,dnim ruoy egnahc uoy fi lleW"
"?reh rof ecnad dna ereht pu teg uoy t'nod yhw ,pmahc ,gnippat swap ruoy ees I
.boj ruoy s'tI .D ,'nikniht syawla er'uoy esuaC'"
.gnikrow er'ew nehw taeh fo tol a tuo tup ew dna sgod mraw yrev era eW"
.yks eht ta pu kool dna ereht yal dna nur a rof tuo og tsuj ll'ew ro ,xaler nac ew ,hguoht ,elihw a ni ecnO" .dennirg eH ".kaerb
alebaS ".thgin rieht otni sruoh owt tuoba er'yeht dna ,detrats ew nehw tuo t'nerew yehT" .dehgis eH
"?tniop eht fo tros taht t'nsI
.sbir eht ni mih dewoble ,sgod dael rieht fo eno ,enaJ
.ecno ta lla egnahc fo deen ni dna detatiga dna tnetnoc dna yppah gnileef m'I .tuo ti gnitros llits m'I sseug I .ko s'tI" .dennirg eH "?he ,ot tnaw t'nod uoy fi ti tuoba klat attog 'nia uoy tuB .D ,yllaer toN"
.gnicnad ruoy deyojne etiuq I dnA"
.gnurps eb thgim ti ekil dekool dna sehcni wef a roolf eht ffo detfil neeb neve dah tI
.dedivorp stlep rieht naht noitcetorp erom deen yeht did rehtaew tsedloc eht ni ylno dna ,sgod nrehtron lla erew yehT
.taef rieht no thgil t'nsaw taht maet eht no god elgnis a t'nsaw ereht hguoht ,eliga tsom eht fo eno osla saw eH
.niaga pu dekcip opmet eht nehw ,seceip neewteb egdirb gninord ,trohs a tsuj ,gnol tsal t'ndid etipser ehT
.emid a no nrut hcum ytterp dluoc ,erew yeht taht sknat ylrub ,sgod leehw eht nevE
,meht fo evif lla ,maet eht no nemow ehT
.won rof walf siht tpecca nac I esoppus I dnA"
"!evom yob ruo ees annaw I .sey
.erutseg sih dewollof alebaS "?srats esoht eeS"
,ynapmoc dexim ylevissergga eht ot noissecnoc a -- stsaerb rieht revo sparw thgil erow
.retniw ni mraw peek sgod dels woh tuo dnif ot dna
.erofeb sepipgab htiw dexim taht draeh reven d'eh tub ,rovalf nital a dah cisum ehT
.ot evom ot doog denmad tlef ti dna gnillepmoc saw tI
.dezeeuqs dna wap reh koot eH "...
,mM" .tnet eht morf mraw llits saw ehs dna ,tfos saw ruf reH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.ecnad a gnidael saw ehs hguoht sa reh wollof ot mih gnignellahc ,seot sih no mih peek ot opmet dna mhtyhr eht htiw deyalp ehs
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop
.tfel I nehw nwod gnidniw tuoba tsuj saw maet eht fo tser ehT .hguone riaF"
.ruf eht gnilffur ,yldnof hgiht sih debbur ehS ".kniht
.emit eht fo hcum edun eht ni dnuora tnew lla yeht ,secived nwo rieht ot tfeL
.shtolc niol ot nwod lla erew yeht :tcaf ni ,tsilaminim yllaeR
.spalf eht hguorht tuo gnillips esion dna htmraw dna thgil rieht ,stnet eht hguorht kcab rehtegot deklaw yehT ".yaw sihT"
;emit emas eht ta devol erew uoy wonk uoy tel dna uoy eldeen dluoc enaJ .srae sih fo eno debbur neht ,daeh eht ni yltneg mih deddorp ehS ".oot ,su fo tser eht rof ereht ni artxe wef a tog uoy kniht I
.elbat eht nwod detuohs dna mih tsap tuo denael ehS ".ereht pu teG
.ecneirepxe hguor a saw sleehw ecivon htiw gnivirD .srenroc hguorht dels eht dellup yllaer ohw seno eht erew yeht taht nevig ,yllaer ,ot daH
.ruf ylleb sih hguorht wap a dehsurb dna dennirg ehS ".ti
"?won tahW" .dehguoc eppillihP
,eno tsrif eht fo ecap eht ot ti edam reven eceip eht elihw dna ,did eH
,emit doog a daH"
.knard eh sa mih gniltsoj ,niaga mih degdun ehS ".boj
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer eb lliw hcihw
.sseltser elttil a gnileef tsuj ebyaM
.wap eerf reh htiw derutseg dna mra sih koot tub ,yllufyalp delbmurg ehS "!ereh uoy evael lliw I" .ffo liart ti tel eH "...yllautca ,lleW" .mra sih dereffo dna detrons eH ".taht
.tnorf sih ot flesreh desserp dna yllacirtaeht derevihs ehS ".mraw
.gninraw tuohtiw eci elbmuj fo hctap a revo mih gnikat ro srenroc dnuora pihw-eht-kcarc gniyalp
.deggurhs eH ".ton esoppus I
.thgin eht otni etal mrofrep ot deludehcs erew stca fo yteirav a erehw egats eht fo weiv taerg a dah tops eht
.kcab rewol sih delffur ehS ".gninrom
"?mraw uoy peek siht t'nseoD" .ruf reh hsurb ot parw fo sreyal reh fo eno rednu gnikaens ,kcab reh gnola wap a debbur eppillihP
.ti devol d'eh dna ,esle enoemos daer ot ytiliba emas taht htiw yalp mih tel dah repip eht rof gnicnaD
.ereht tuo flesruoy fo tseb eht teg uoy pleh ot gniyrt saw ehs wenk uoy -- redael doog a hcus reh edam taht sgniht eht fo eno saw ti thguoht eppillihP
.truh eht ezisahpme ot tsehc sih ot wap a tup eH .esneffo kcom htiw deilper eh ",enaJ ,boj ym tsuj naht erom m'I"
?os kniht t'nod I" .deggurhs eH ".rennid
.kaerb ruoy no nac uoy sa peels hcum sa
,nehctik eht ni dnuof eb netfo nac eh ,gnitirw ton nehW
.maet eht no sgod lacisyhp erom eht fo eno saw enaJ
.deilppus ti enilanerda fo tloj eht deyojne eh timda d'eh ,desserp fi ,dna ,ti eldnah dluoc eh wenk yehT
.evisiced dna ,deredisnoc ,tnegilletni
.kcab dna sedis sih revo ruf eht hguorht gnimaor swap reh
.niaga revo mih dekool ehS ".retteb
.ssik a rof nwod elzzum sih dellup dna daeh sih fo kcab eht ot pu wap a deppils dna detrons alebaS
eppillihP .tnet reh otni deraeppasid dna denrut neht dna pih sih dettap ehs taht htiW ".ereht eb ,renniD"
.kcab gnikniht ,desuap ehS ".puorg
dias ehs gnihtyreve edam taht kool dedispol tahwemos a dah ehs os ,dekrep reven dah rae eno dna seye reh fo eno dnuora ruf fo hctap kcalb a dah ehS
,mih hsup ot dediced yeht nehw dna doom rieht gnidaer ,maet eht htiw gniniart morf tnereffid os ton saw tI
.htooms yrev tuB
"?eb taht nac woH ?mraw ooT"
.noitalletsnoc a tuo detniop eppillihP .yks thgin eht derimda yeht sa ecnelis elbatrofmoc a otni nellaf dah noitasrevnoc rieht dna ,desuap d'yehT  ".no dael od ,seY"
.wonk uoy dedulcni er'yehT" .detrons ehS ".taert
ydolem citnarf-tsomla na gniliaw sepip ,tsaf dna toh nar tI .mih ediug cisum eht tel dna thgiew sih knas neht ,roolf eht no tuo ti gnippat ,wap sih htiw taeb eht dnuof eppillihP .eceiphtuom eht dnuora kcab dennirg ehS .mih dniheb gaw wols a gnivig liat sih ,reh ta dennirg eh dna ,deyalp ehs sa mih gnieye repipgab eht thguac eH .hguoht ,tnereffid saw cisum ehT
.esnopser ni ylthgil deredduhs eppillihP dna ,kcab sih fo llams eht revo ylthgil swalc reh deggard alebaS ".sllac
"?tnet eht ot kcab sepip ym ekat uoy dluoc ,náoX" ,denrut ehS ".oB" ".os hcum yreV"
.niaga rae reh deppin dna dennirg eH
:egats no emac dnab rehtonA ".ereht
"!em ot lla ta esnes on sekaM ?dloc eht ni ecneidua na rof sgniht yvaeh gniluaH"
.delkcuhc dna ylprahs hgiht sih dettap enaJ
.sworbeye reh desiar
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,trohs a tuo tel dna sepip reh detalfni dah egats no hctib ehT
"?ecnad dna pu teg dluohs ereh D kniht ,alleH ,iO"
.staeb tnereffid no roolf eht gnikirts dna spih sih gniyaws ,ylwols erom gnivom ,decnad eh sa swap nwo sih gnippalc dna daeh sih yb swap sih gnitfil
.thgin eht fo dloc psirc dna ssenkcalb hctip eht rof dniheb htmraw esolc dna thgil eht gnivael ,detrats tog tca txen eht erofeb tnet niam eht fo tuo deppils yehT
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
;krow fo enil ruo ni lufesU" .reh ta dennirg eppillihP ".lliks a etiuq s'tahT"
".rennid teg dna pu naelc neht ,os ro evif litnu nur dna thgie ta trats ll'eW .yad lla ,dnik si rehtaew eht fI"
"?eerf er'uoy neht dnA"
.ydal'm ,esruoc fo tuB"
.drawrof maet eht gnivom ot gnitubirtnoc t'nsaw netfo eh os ,nar yeht sa decnalab dels eht peek ot boj sih saw ti
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,etades erom saw eceip sihT
".sknahT" .keehc reh ta deson dna dennirg eH ".sreeb
.thgiE" "?ti si nehW"
"?klaw taht ekat ew llahS"
.niaga hgiht sih dezeeuqs neht ,deggurhs enaJ
"!nwod em toohs uoy dna ecin eb ot gniyrt m'I ereH
,mmM" ".kcolc eht no t'nera uoy esuac' tsuj 'nikniht pots t'nod uoy tuB .erus ,eruS"
.detrap yeht ,dnim sih ni noos oot raf ,yllautnevE .tem seugnot rieht dna meht detrap eH
?ereH" .wap a devaw ehS ".sseltser
.senord wef oot dah ti ekil dekool taht epipgab a gniyrrac
.rennid ta ffo elttil a dekool uoY
"?elttil yrev os raew yeht taht morf emoc uoy od erehW ?uoy dnA" .revo mih dekool god ehT ". renroc tsewhtron s'añapsE eht era eW !sah enoyna yldraH" .mih ta dennirg ehS
.erew shtolc niol rieht sa emas eht hcum
.gnirehtag eht fo tniop elohw eht saw taht ,esruoc fO .doog tub
.gnihtemos yas dluohs eh derugif eppillihP
"?wonk uoy ,taht ekil leef t'nseod ti tuB .si ti esoppus I"
.gnicnivnoc hcum dedeen yllaer
?uoy gnitae gnihtyna oS"
.ecap tneced a ekil gnihtyna peek ot yrt ew fi gniyd tsuj er'ew ,gnizeerf woleb seerged wef a naht remraw steg ti nehW
-- hguoht ,deganam yehT
.emit elohw eht decnad eppillihP dna ,revo saw tes rieht litnu seceip erom wef a deyalp dnab ehT
.oot ,peels ylbaborp dluohs I"
.ti ta pu gnirats ,tnemom a rof doots yeht dna ,meht evoba dehcterts yaW ykliM eht fo hcra ehT
uoy rof daer dna nettirw
.ylegas deddon alleH ".enoemos
"?ynapmoc rof gnikooL ?haeY"
.ti fo reffo na gnikam ,elbat eht rednu hgiht sih dettap ehS
.gninrom ylrae na evah eW .tuo ssap tsuj ll'I kniht I" .deggurhs eppillihP
.t'nac I tuo dnif ot dellirht eb ll'I !haH" .detrons ehS
"?netfo ti ees uoy od
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
.maet sih htiw elip delgnat ,gib a otni gnitteg dna evird a morf kcab gnimoc ekil hcum t'nsaw ereht timda ot dah eppillihP .rehto hcae dnA
.rekram llacer-fo-dne fo tros lacisyhp a ,dne eht ta deddon ehS ".smurd
".eppillihP" .dellortnoc dna mrif saw pirg reH
.ruf taorht sih otni htaerb reh tuo gniwolb ,deffuh ehS ".won
".dnuora gnidnats eb tsuj ll'I dnA .on ,mraw taht toN"
.elbuort ekil dnuos
.tnet s'maet sih dnif ot ffo deppets dna dennirg eH .deggaw liat sih dna pu dekrep srae sih ,meht dnuof d'eh ecnO
.ojod eht ro ,pohs eht
.ereht eugra annog ton m'I"
.meht fo epahs eht gnicart ,derutseg dna delkcuhc eH ".sey
",hctiblleH" dellac ylriafnu ro yltneuqerfni ton ,god dael rehto eht ,alleH
.parw reh revo gnihsiws ,reh dniheb gaw a evag liat nwo reH ".gnicnad
"?klaw a ekat ot eraC
enuT .flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
.mraw peek ot yaw emos dnif ot evah ll'uoY .salA"
.irauR nosmirC yb
.dekramer eppillihP ",taht gniees fo derit teg reven I ,kcuF"
".reh rof pu tiaw ot gniog ton m'I
"?D giB ,tuoba 'nikniht ahctahW"
,niapS ,aicilaG ,sañatnom sad nózaroC ,eesseL" .tops eht no drow rof drow troper liart yreve tuoba tsuj rebmemer dluoc ehs -- dael taerg a reh edam taht rotcaf rehtona ,yromem fo tros taht dah enaJ
.ecno ta lla semitemos ,enoyna htiw tpels enoyna erehw ,gniog laed ylimaf nepo fo tros a dah nwonk d'eh smaet tsoM
.elzzum sih fo tuo gnignah eugnot sih ,gninnirg flesmih dnuof eppillihP
".lufrednow saw gniyalp ruoY .tsiser t'ndluoc I" .mih dniheb deyaws liat sih dna ,kcab dennirg eH ".ti
.pu peek ot mih gnirad ,retsaf taeb eht dehsup ehs dna dehsalf seye reH
".pu deldnub eb ll'I
.hgU" .taht ot noitcaer s'ydob sih eciton d'ehs erus saw eh dna ,mih tsniaga doog yrev tlef ehS
.siht slavir tI" .reh ta deddon eH ".lufrednow
.ruf etihw reh htiw gnitsartnoc doow krad eht ,hteet reh neewteb ylthgil thguac eceiphtuom eht ,niaga mih ta gninnirg repip eht dnuof eH
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna 1 WALC dna
41 taeH ni seirots trohs sah eH
.ti deyojne uoy dalg m'I
.wob-flah a evag dna kcab pets a koot eH "?kcab em klaW
"?won siht s'tahw ,hO" .pu dekrep eppillihP
.puorg naicilaG emos saw ti dias eludehcs ehT" .delkcuhc enaJ
.sllac ytud tub ,wonk I ,emahs A"
;gnicnad uoy was I !ereht yeh hO" .mih ta delims ehs dna ,yawa sepip reh gnittup tsuj saw ehS
t'ndah eH .ecnad ot doog eb d'ti dnA .evom ot tnaw mih edam cisum eht yned t'ndluoc eH ".ko ,kO"
.esruoc fo ,enaJ rof tpecxE
.tcefrep eb t'nac I esoppus I .llew hA"
,esolc flesreh desserp dna daeh reh koohs ehS ".ecap
.hpmH" .pu daeh sih deppit yksuh ehT ".wonk
noitartsnomed gniddels a rof emit txen ni
"?ti si niapS ni erehW .erofeb aicilaG fo draeh reven ev'I"
".em ewo ll'uoY .aroñes ,íS" .deddon tub ,reh ta dennirg náoX neeb evah tsum ohw god ehT
.spil sih ta yltneg deyalp eugnot reh dna ,gnol dna ,mraw saw tI
".ysub eb ll'uoy ecnis ,od ot evah ll'tI .taoc a evah I" .detrons ehS
.dennirg dna daeh reh dekcoc ehS ".ylevoL .eppillihP"
.rae reh fo pit eht ta ylthgil deppin dna dennirg eH ".mraw
.enoemos htiw deb ni pmuj tsuj t'nod uoy semitemos ,wonk'Y .llew ,haeY" .dehguoc eH ".og ot ydaer llits s'yob sihT .doog oot ton tuB" .htolc eht hguorht mih dezeeuqs dna dennirg ehS "?he
.kniht I ,thginot toN .haN" .hguoht ,daeh sih koohs eH
.nuf rof seirots dna
.eppillihP ,sedutitlum niatnoc od erus uoY" .hgual a fo krab trohs a evag enaJ ".ecno
gnivil a rof erawtfos setirw nosmirC
:redael prahs denmad a osla saw ehS
teg nac uoy os nac uoy sa kciuq sa tuo ssap uoy dna tae dna pmac ekam uoy ,hcterts a nur uoy ,semitemos ,hcihW
.deredisnoc eh sa knird rehtona koot eppillihP
.emit doog a dah d'eh sngis ylno eht t'nerew liat gniggaw a dna seye thgirb taht noitavresbo na htiw mih deteerg alleH ,palf eht hguorht deppets eh nehW
.ruf sih hguorht spit walc tnulb reh gnillup ,edis sih revo dekorts alebaS ".worromot omed ruo erofeb peels emos teg ot evah I dna etal gnitteg s'tI" .dehgis eH ".pirt
".adanaC" .dehguoc eppillihP
.sgoD delS naidanaC dalc-ylitnacs tuoba erom raeh ot evol d'I"
.spih reh no swap sih gnitser ,niaga reh decaf eppillihP ,detacidni ehs eno eht ta devirra yeht nehW
.ereht tuo sdeb on ,eno roF"
.kool tsilaminim a rof detpo d'yeht ,yawrednu gniniart rieht dna ni nworg stlep retniw s'maet sih htiw dna ,mraw saw tnet eht ,seidob fo sserp eht htiW
.gnitnirps neeb d'eh ekil gnitnap mih dah ti tub ,setunim fo lufdnah a detsal ylno eceip ehT
.alebaS em llaC" .wap a tuo kcuts ehS ".os tsuJ"
.taht rof tah thgir eht gniraew t'nera uoY" .edis sih debbaj ehS ".ydal'm
.ot detnaw eh taht toN
.mraw oot tsomla eb ll'ti retal hcum og ew fI
,irauR nosmirC yb ”delS naicilaG“
.ynapmoc emos esu dluoc yeht ekil kool ohw shtimskcalb emos ees I ,em woN !oG
.ti htaeneb gnola gnivird smurd htiw
.tnemom a rof reh ta dennirg eH ".htooms
.ti seod ehs woh wonk t'nod I"
.pu kool ot rebmemer ew revenehW"
.lufrednow sdnuos tahT" .deddon alebaS ".yks
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.reh ta nwod dennirg eppillihP ".ynapmoc
".worromot ysub eb annog er'uoy ,D ,eyetuhs emos barg lleW"
.retal seenk sih no ysae dna
.dloc eht deciton neve t'ndah eH
"?ew llahS" .eppillihP ot denrut ehS ".llahs ylniatrec I"
,ni denioj eppillihP
.reeb sih fo knird a dniheb nirg a dih eH "?gnihtyna tuoba gnikniht m'I syas ohW"
.htaehs sih fo tuo yaw a etiuq deppils d'eh dezilaer eh dna ,htolc niol sih fo tnorf eht dettap ehS
.ti ecarbme ot retteb dekrow tsuj ti ,edun eht ni emit hcum os tneps dna esolc os dna lacisyhp os tsuj erew yehT
.taeb eht tnecca ot swap sih deppalc dna tnelis og murd sih tel sremmurd eht fo eno dna
... uoy teem ot erusaelp a s'tI
.taorht sih ta pin ot pu elzzum reh deppit ehS ".tcefrep
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.flesti ni erutnevda na saw elbat eht ot knird dna doof gnitteg dna ,selbat rehto eht neewteb ecaps lanosrep fo tol a evah yltcaxe t'ndid maet sih fo sgod thgie rehto eht dna eppillihP
!dooG" .taws a pmur sih evag enaJ
.egats eht fo tnorf ni tops raelc eht drawot dworc eht hguorht yaw sih dekrow ylwols dna reh tfel eppillihP ".t'nac
.fo eman eht wonk t'ndid eppillihP tnemurtsni dekcen-gnol ,deidob-xob fo tros emos dna smurd okiat llams fo elpuoc a ekil dekool tahw gniyalp erew egats eht no sgod fo puorg A
.smurd dna )sepipgab( atiag
hctib delzzum-rednels a dna smurd fo stros tnereffid gniyrrac owt ,sehtolc lufroloc ni sgod derae-ytniop ,detaoc-maerc fo oirt a
.mra sih tsniaga denael dna ,sregnif rieht gniniwtretni ,sih otni wap reh pils ot noitnettani sih fo egatnavda koot alebaS
.detacided tsom eht rof tpecxe ,noitasrevnoc tuo denword tsomla dna ecaps eht dellif tI
.daeh sih koohs dna dennirg eppilihP
.mih rof looc ti gniyalp oN .deggaw liat siH
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna eseht piks nac uoy
.pirt siht rof gniniart fo trap sa strahc eht ta dekool ew
.hcneb eht morf flesmih gnitcartxe ,doots dna dehgis eH
.rennid retfa ,won morf sthgin owT"
?thgir ,nur a no maet eht htiw gnieb naht tnereffid hcum taht t'nsaw ti ,deggurhs eH
".yllaer ,hcum gnihtoN"
,,irauR nosmirC yb ”delS naicilaG“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht eht saw sihT
.doom eht ni t'nsaw eh fi neve ecin tlef tI
.oot ,mih dnif seye s'esle enoyreve leef dluoc eh neht dna ,roolf ecnad eht otno sserp eht fo tuo deppets eh sa mih no seye s'maet sih leef dluoc eH
:ykcul neeb d'yehT
.liart eht no tuo sknuhc hsif nezorf dna pols taem nwod gniflow ot derapmoc suoiruxul saw ti
.liat sih htiw tnemevom eht gniretnuoc ,spih sih fo yaws eht detareggaxe dna kcab dennirg eH
,tnereffiD .doog dednuos tI
.elttil a tsuj reh otni kcab gninael ,dexaler neht ,esirprus ni ylfeirb deneffits eH