.mih ta elzzum deppit-rosicni tnaig reh don ot hguone gnol skoob reh morf pu dekool ehS
dneirf tseb reh htiw gnivil eb ot gniog saw trap tseb eht raf yb tub
”.gnihtemos dias evah dluohs dna eeffoc eht revo gnissesbo uoy was I
.thgir saw boB taht timda ot dah ehs hguohtla
.sdop neerg llams htiw dellif saw tI
.detcepxe naht reivaeh saw top ehT
.teef evif s’racsO naht rellat ylerab ,dnik sti fo eno rof trohs saw namuh ehT
?ffo em pot uoy dluoC“
,don etilop a racsO dereffo eH
.tuoba repap eht gnivaw ,dias maS ”,revaeb a m’I
”,sehtolc wen uoy yub ll’I .yrroS“
,sgniw htiw drazil tnaig a gnidir srae egnarts htiw snamuh fo krowtra lacitsatnaf dah reh ot tsesolc draobdrac eht fo edis ehT
,reh fo tnorf ni talf tas ti taht os sgel reh neewteb liat reh kcuts d’ehS
.ssalg dna eeffoc htiw roolf eht dna ,sdraobpuc eht ,ynnoR
”.neht detrats top rehtona teg ll’I“
.dlof dnasuoht a desaercni llems eht nottub trats eht tih eh sA
.esirprus ni reh ta deknilb ohw ,racsO ta gnitniop ,deksa maS
,lewot aet a tuo dellup dna sreward dehsalps-eeffoc eht fo eno denepo racsO dnah rehto sih htiW
.ytpme won saw ti taht ynnoR wohs ot gum reh gnitlit ,deksa ehs
.gnihtyreve dna etunim tsal si siht taht dnatsrednu I ,ton fI
.roolf tew eht no gnikaeuqs selos eohs rebbur
,tib tsal eht gnilley saw ehs litnu esor eciov reh
.taes daeh eht fo tnorf ni elbat eht no ni dial eh erehw
.daeh sih koohs dna ti fo pot eht revo dnah a tup racsO tub ,gum s’maS pu kcip ot tnew namuh ehT
.laed gib on s’ti ,haeY“
,desuap neht ,roolf eht gnippom nageb racsO
.niaga dezzub mocretni ehT
”.gnipeels era srobhgien ym dna thgindim s’tI“
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.neht ,boB eb ll’tahT“
taes reh fo tuo decnuob yllacitcarp maS ”!esaelp ,seY“
”.ylkciuq og lliw ti pleh lla ew fI“
.yllautca ,erofeb eeffoc dah reven ev’I ,oN“
,sllaw eht hguorht ylisae delevart secafrus drah no sevooh fo polc-pilc eht yltnerappA
,delbmum ehs ”,sey ,uoy rof retcarahc tcefrep eht evah I kniht I“
”?racsO .eeffoc erom
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”,mu ,tsuJ .enif m’I“
.maS sa llat sa saw ehs taht os deklaw ehs sa pu gnihcterts sgel gnol reh
,waN“ ”.lla retfa ,eeffoc sih s’tI
.dekooc ti sa eeffoc eht fo llems eht gniyojne ,nehctik eht otni tnew dna riahc reh fo tuo depmuj maS ,werb ot eeffoc eht rof detiaw ehs elihW
.wap reh htiw dnah rieht koohs dna dehcterts ehS ”.maS m’I ,olleH“
”?yawyna ,siht si emag fo dnik tahW“
”.taht htiw uoy pleh nac I ,ereH“
.noos evirra ot eud erew ohw
eht ot detlit loots eht neht dna egde eht revo tnew teef reh fo eno fo seot ehT
,ylthgils ylno tub ,rettib saw tI
,ksa ot tnaw t’ndid maS
,hguod edam-erp morf seikooc yldneirf-erovibreh
.snroh gnol sih fo eno htiw daeh reh deppob yltnedicca d’eh semit wef a dna gniddon neeb dah daeh gib siH
.elims a reh dereffo boB ”.hguone riaF“
,nehctik eht ot ecnartne eht ni doots boB
.ssem eht ta kcohs ni gnirats nehctik eht ot yawrood eht ni doots ydnaM dna
,relleK nosidaM naI yb ”thgiN emaG“ saw sihT
.yldipar gnilooc saw regna reh tub ,deddon maS
.gnixim saw ehs pid eht otni deloord tsomla ehS
”?thgin lla retaw poop gniknird neeb ev’I“
.yenom ruoy gnikat ton m’I ,ydnaM ,oN“
”.noitanod sih etaicerppa yllaer eW“
.s’ynnoR sa hgih sa tsomla saw daeh sih taht os riahc eht no gnidnats ,ynnoR ot txen taes eht koot dna deddon eH
.riahc eht fo doow eht no yllacimhtyhr deppals liat eht fo dne talf eht dna
.ylhsipeehs dias maS ”,yrroS“
”?thginot su htiw gnimag eb ll’uoy ti ekat I oS“
.moor gnivil eht ni namuh a ot txen gnidnats racsO ees ot gniknilb pu dekool maS  .dias eciov a
.emit siht demaercs ehs ”!TAHW“
,moor gninid eht otni deirrac dna gab reh pu dekcip racsO
.llat pu dnats ot enips sih gninethgiarts ,pu denethgirb boB
.reh ot ti dewohs dna tekcop tekcaj sih fo tuo eiggab citsalp llams a dellup boB
.ruf reh fo tser eht fo roloc nworb thgil eht hctam ot pu-ekam nworb yb neddih saw elzzum s’airtun a derevoc evah dluohs taht ruf etihw ehT
”.lacihte erom hcum si ti etapicitrap ot rehtehw esoohc nac ew taht woN
.seye kcalb ynihs sih htiw reh ta gniralg ,wap a tuo dleh boB ”,woN“
.racsO ot gninrut erofeb emoh wen reh dnuora dekool maS
.llems gnizama eht fo noitaicerppa reporp ni liat reh pals dluoc dna
.kcapkcab reh ffo detfeh dna rediw neve dennirg ydnaM ”?yllaer ,hO“
.rednirg cirtcele na otni snaeb eht ruop racsO dehctaw ehs sa detanicsaf ,deksa maS ”?taht si tahW“
.ti fo mottob eht otni gnippird ylwols saw snaeb eht sa llems enivid emas eht dah taht diuqil kraD .enihcam eht fo mottob eht ot dehcatta efarac eht tsniaga regnif-devooh a deppat racsO ”.ecnarelot
.seye reh dediova dna daeh sih dekcud eH
,mih gnixaler naht rehtaR
,depleh gnivom ehT
.gnitnar dna gniliaw
,robhgien doog eht syawla ,racsO dna
.moordeb eht fo noitcerid eht ni deklaw ylregnig ynnoR ”.sknahT“
.werb fo level eht kcehc ot deppoh ehs hguorht dessap ehs emit hcaE
.ti ekil uoy dalG .ma I“
.neve ,taerG .doog neeb dah tI
.reh ta dennirg eH
.kcab deddon eh dna
,nrocpop edam yehT
.dewollaws ehs sa taorht reh demraw dna eugnot reh no hcir dna htooms saw eeffoc ehT
.kniw a htiw reh ta derepsihw egats ynnoR ”,reh dnim t’noD“
.sdneirf ym fo emos teem dna su nioj ot uoy rof evol d’I tub
,sdneirf s’racsO lla fo seman eht rebmemer ot gniyrt ,gnisufnoc tib a saw tI
”?ti ekat I ,erofeb epyt siht dah t’nevaH“
.ti otni pom eht degnulp dna nehctik eht yb tekcub eht tes racsO
”.ees ll’uoy ,hu ,lleW
.racsO dna ydnaM gniwollof ,deksa maS ”?retsam emaG“
.loots a no saw ehs nettogrof d’ehs tuB
.tellaw reh desolc dna dehgis maS ”?yenom yM“
.ffuts siht ot desu ton er’uoy ,maS“
.ynnoR dna reh ffo gnihsurb hsinif racsO tel dna daeh reh gnuh maS
.emit ni tsuj dekcud ohw ,ynnoR gnittih gnissim ylworran ,moor eht ssorca dna wap reh fo tuo welf gum reH .revo gnippit morf peek ot gniyrt ,smra reh delialf ehs ylevitcnitsnI .edis
.rehto eht ni eeffoc fo gum lluf-flah eht dna wap eno ni repap fo eceip eht pu dekcip maS ”.eniF“
,gniht-lesaew ehT
maS sdrawot pets a koot racsO
.roolf eht revo lla dna ruf reh gnola derettilg ssalg fo sdrahS
.yltcerroc dellacer ehs fi ,rekrow-oc A
,tuo teef reh daerps ehs dna ,retnuoc eht fo edis eht no sdraobpuc eht tih liat reH
.trihs dialp reh fo tekcop tnorf eht fo tuo tellaw a gud dna moorb reh nwod tup ydnaM
.ylthgirb dias maS ”,nalp eht s’tahT“
,regguR .P .B yb uoy rof daer
.muelonil s’nehctik eht no neve dnuos elttil edam
.retcarahc neg-erp a yalp ot evah uoy gninraw em evig t’ndid racsO ecniS“
.seirrehc eeffoc eht tae ,em ekil ,stac teviC mlaP
.ti werdhtiw eh erofeb dnah s’racsO no wap a ecalp dluoc ehs os won rof ti derongi ehs tub
.segaw s’keew a naht erom saw tahT
.gum s’maS ot detfihs noitnetta riehT
.gum ytpme won reh pu dleh maS
”.werb suoiciled siht rof elbisnopser er’uoy raeh I“
.gum nwo rieht otni top eht fo tser eht deruop dna deggurhs ynnoR sa ylmulg dehctaw dna taes reh ni nwod depmuls ehS ”.thgirlA“
.ssalg nekorb eht fo sseldeeh
”,detrats ytrap siht teg s’teL“
.tluciffid saw ti tub
.spotretnuoc sih hcaer dluoc ehs taht os lootspets a maS thguob dna daeha thguoht dah racsO
,nosrep eno rof dezis neeb dah ecalp reH
,secnalg deirrow reh evag yllanoisacco racsO
”.namuh a saw elbaliava dah I tahw dnA
.mih draehsim evah ot dah ehS
.deddon maS ”.ereh tiaw uoY
.elzzum reh fo egde eht no dehcrep taht sessalg kciht dna
,repap eht ta kool ot deirt ehs sa koohs swap reh ,revewoH
.swap erab nwo reh ekil toN
”.skcans eht teg neht dna
.eeffoc gnillems suoiciled fo elddup a ni dednal ti erehw ,roolf eht ot eldnah citsalp eht deppord maS ”?tahW“
.retnuoc eht no pu ti tes dna sdraobpuc reppu sih fo eno morf tuo enihcam gnikool-detacilpmoc a dellup racsO nehT
.elbat eht ssorca tuo dnah rieht kcuts dna reh morf ssorca taes eht ni tas ynnoR
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.yrroS“ ”.noitnetta yaP
.ddo s’tI“ ”.gnimag rO
.reh ta syawedis kool ot ria eht otni elzzum niht gnol sih gnitfil
.srae dnuor ,llams reh neewteb daeh eht no ssik a reh evig ot revo denael dna kcab delims eH
.nwod seenk eht morf nworb erew yeht dna ,tsedrah eht snaej reh tih dah eeffoc ehT
,nooccar a fo taht ot ralimis seye sih ssorca ruf fo ksam depirts kcalb a dah ,boB
.trihstaews ’skcuD nogerO yggab a erow dna
,mih truh t’ndluow tI
”.eeffoc raluger ekil ,ti tsaor neht dna tuo ti kcip eW
”.reggiD maS ,dneirflrig ym si siht ,ydnaM“
”.tsal ta uoy teem yllanif ot desaelP
,sevooh sih htiw ton
”.ti dellips ohw eno eht s’ehS
”?huh ,trap taht uoy llet ot togrof I ,hO“ .gnicniw
”,noitanigami fo emag a s’ti ,uoy dlot I“
.ffo decnuob ti sa ecnalab reh peek ot gniyrt
.daeh sih gnihctulc dna seenk sih ot gnippord ,deliaw boB ”!eeffoc yM“
”.thgin emag si thginot togrof I tub
.wap rehto reh ni pu gnidloh saw ehs repap eht ta kool neve t’ndid ehs taht etsat eht ni pu thguac os saw ehS .lufrednoW
,racsO ot rovaf a sa ,eniF“
,seohs erow ,nees reve d’ehs snamuh lla ekil ,ynnoR dna
.daeh reh koohs maS
pu dellup spalf eht htiw pac kcajrebmul dialp der a htiw ffo deppot saw tiftuo reh dna ,snaej mined erow ehS
.reilrae thguob dah racsO spihc allitrot fo gab eht htiw og ot pid odacova dna
.reh ot elbat eht ssorca repap fo eceip a gnidils ,reh ta dekniw dna dennirg ydnaM
,pis rehtona koot maS
”.emit nuf a rof ni er’uoy ,lleW“
.emag eht no sucof ot hguone llits peek ot delggurts llits ehs tub
.repap eht revo dekool ehs elihw pis a koot ehS
.pu tuc teef reh gnivah morf efas osla saw dna
?mih ot taht nevig evah uoy t’ndluohS“
,uoy egrahc t’now I
,hA“ .dezzub rood ehT
,etal gnitteg s’ti ecnis ,deb ot og ot tnaw dna derit er’uoy fi dnatsrednu I“
.gniyduts thgin lla pu yats ot deen uoy nehw lufesu s’tI“
.srepap reh morf pu gnikool tuohtiw dias ydnaM ”,ees ll’uoY“
.poop eht ni tuo semoc naeb eht fo trap os ti fo lla tsegid t’nac ew tub ,tcart evitsegid ruo hguorht seog tI
.nooM ooM elbaffeni eht
.revo lla yrettij tlef ehs ,tcaf nI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.daer ehs sa gel reh elggij dluoc ehs os taes eht ni pu doots dna elbat eht ot egap eht denettalf ehS
.eeffoc fo top ytpme tsomla eht no desucof erom saw maS tub ,enoyreve ot steehs repap dnuora dessap ydnaM .elbat eht no tfel dah ynnoR taht top eht morf dellif eh hcihw ,mih htiw gum ytpme na dah eH
.snaeb eht tae ot meht gnicrof snamuh eht htiw ,stevic eht fo evitatiolpxe yllaer eb ot desu ti ,haeY“ .sdrow s’racsO ot gnola gniddon saw boB
.gnittis nehw hcuorc yllarutan tsum ehS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.taht wonk uoy ,ycaciled enif a si eeffoc kawuL ipoK“
,em htiw hcum taht evah t’nod I“
daeh rieht morf gnituorps sredluohs rieht fo spot eht dehsurb taht ruf nworb dah yehT
,sdneirf wen reh yllufepoh
.enihcam eht ot resolc saw loots reh dehsiw maS
.noitcerid s’ynnoR ni gum ytpme na gnihsup ,neercs eht dnuora deraeppa wap s’ydnaM ”.eerht ,eM“
.maS ta detniop boB
,yltsom si ti ,lleW“
,relleK nosidaM naI yb ”thgiN emaG“
.teehs s’nidalap namuh reh pu dekcip dna nwod kcab tas maS  ”.ko ,hO“
.nwonk t’ndah ehs taht meht ot derrucco t’ndah ylbaborp ti dna
,emos evah nac uoY“
”.erom evah uoy erofeb sruoh wef a ti eviG
dna retnuoc eht ni saw top eeffoc eht erehw fo tnorf ni doots ehS
,mmH“ .nehctik eht ni ssem eht ta decnalg dna deffins eH
.dlrow eht ni tseb eht ti llac emoS
.rehtie ,lesaew a ton tub ,neht nooccar a ton ,oS
.yltnetni yrev teehs eht gniyduts erew uoY
.retcarahc ruoy si siht ,ereH“
.ydnaM ot tsesolc taes eht otni pu debmilc dna deggurhs maS
,mih retfa delddaw ydnaM
.remocwen eht ot devaw ehs daetsni os
.ti htiw railimaf t’nsaw maS epyt a fo lesaew egral a gnidael retal setunim wef a ni emac racsO
”?eeffoc taht si ,hO
.boB ot detniop dna pu tas ehS ”.tiaW“
.gnitagitsevni erew rentrap reh dna ehs emirc revetahw dettimmoc yeht nehw evah dluow yeht ekil kniht ot gniyrt ,tcepsus eht saw ehs gninigami
,sretcarahc rieht fo seman eht dna
.emag eht gniyojne saw ehS
.nuf gnivah saw maS dna
,ykahs eciov sih ,deunitnoc dna ,htaerb peed a koot racsO
,enog saw eh elihW
,egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”?uoy ewo I od hcum woh ,oS“
,seceip dnasuoht a otni derettahs dna hsarc duol a htiw daeh reh ot txen roolf eht otni dehsams eeffoc fo top ssalg ehT
.depleh ecalp s’retcarahc reh ni flesreh gninigami dna emag eht fo selur eht no gnitartnecnoC
.tekcub a dna pom a htiw deraeppaer racsO
,sreppils-esuoh deddap sih ni desacne ,sevooh siH
”?sehtolc emos worrob I fi dnim ,racsO“
.teprac eht morf hcaer dluoc ehs sdrahs ssalg eht pu gnipeews nageb ydnaM elihw reh ta gniralg llits saw boB
”.retsam emag ruo si ydnaM“
.nehctik eht deretne d’yeht nehw no meht tup dah
.gab reh morf skoob dna srepap gnikcapnu nageb dna elbat eht fo daeh eht ta taes eht otni pu depmuj ydnaM
.tekcub eht htiw moorhtab eht otni tnew racsO
.rehto eht htiw gum reh dna wap eno htiw top eht rof gnihcaer ,ti no depmuj dna revo loots reh dehsup maS
,lleW“ .tnecs eht rovas ot seye reh gnisolc ,htaerb peed a koot maS
,reh gnihsalps
,ssem eht hguorht deppolc dna sreppils esuoh sih ffo deppils racsO ”?yako owt uoy erA .boB ,eeffoc eht tuoba dnim reveN“
,txen tuo emac ynnoR
.boB ot denrut racsO
.deticxe os saw ehs ynnoR ta gum reh werht tsomla ehs dna
”.ynnoR ro boB eb ll’taht
.sgum gnimaets owt htiw moor gninid eht deretne-er eh sa delbmurg racsO ”,haey ,haeY“
.boB eb tsum uoy ,iH“
.thgir neeb dah ynnoR ,yletanutrofnU
.moorb a tuo dellup dna tesolc llah eht denepo ydnaM
.tnedicca na rof yap maS ekam t’nod ,kooL“
.hteet sih fo pans a htiw ti gnihctac dna ria eht otni yrrehc eeffoc war a gnikcilf ,dias boB ”,em rof enoN“
stneicnA eht fo lautiR
”.egelloc ni saw I nehw ti rof etsat a deriuqca I tub
?yalp yllausu uoy od semag draob tahW
,puorg a sa krow ew fI“
.flesmih ti sekam boB
”?snamuh rof ylno saw eeffoc thguoht I“
.sdraobpuc eht otni dehsams tI
.nehctik eht fo tuo delddaw dna loots reh ffo depmuj maS ,suoiruC
.reh htiw retnuoc eht ffo eeffoc fo top eht gniggard ,rehto eht tnew ehs dna yaw eno tnew loots ehT
”--puc elgnis a rof snaeb hguone tuo poop ot syad em sekat tI“
.htuom sih otni ti deppop dna ,sdop eht fo eno tuo dekcip ,gab eht denepo eh taht htiW
.suomaf dlrow si eeffoc siH
.wap eno htiw sessalg reh pu gnihsup ,dias ydnaM
,no won morf luferac erom eb ll’ehS
”?edam s’ti woh wonk uoy oD“
.mutnemom erom flesreh evig ot tnemevom eht htiw liat reh gnigniws
,eldnah citsalp kcalb eht deppirg llits maS
,niaga deffins boB
.suoiciled saw eeffoc ehT
.kcab reh devaw eh dna mih wollof ot devom maS
.ylthgils ylno detfihs efarac ssalg ehT
.mih ta pu delims dna nwod ti dewollaws ehs tub ,ssensuovren s’racsO ta dehgual tsomla maS
.hcum oot knird ot ton erus ekam tub
.maS ,knom s’racsO“ ”?ohw ,tiaW“
.eugnot reh ta depparcs dna deggag maS
”,taK ipoK ehT ,pohs ym tuo kcehc emoc dluohs uoY
,eldnah eht hcaer dluoc dnah s’ynnoR erofeb tuo top eht deknay maS ”.ti od nac I ,oN“ ”—vaeh s’tI“
,nrohgnoL saxeT a rof hguone gib ton yletinifed dna
.ragus fo enotrednu teews eht dna gnat yttun a yb derewoprevo saw taht dna
.sllifer ydnaM dna reh deruop dna elbat eht ot kcab top eeffoc eht thguorb ynnoR ,ylikcuL
.flesreh naht retrohs elttil a airtun a eb ot tuo denrut ydnaM
,dellac ehs reduol
.rehtom sti morf gnignah tik a ekil ti revo depard ehS
,3102 ecnis gnitirw neeb sah ohw
,thgin eht gnirud ti knurd lla d’yeht yaw eht yb ,laed gib a saw ti thguoht meht fo enon ylsuoivbO
”,gnimoc erew uoy em dlot dah racsO fI .esac ni tsuj
”.yltcaxe ,tey si emag eht tahw em dlot t’nsah racsO hguohtlA“
.retcarahc eht dekil uoy woh deksa I“ ”?taht saw tahW“
”?namuh si retcarahc ym syas siht ,tiaW“
relleK nosidaM naI yb
.retaw gninnur fo dnuos eht revo moorhtab eht morf dessih racsO ”,hhhhS“ ”!tuo pooP“
”.s’nhoJ weN ni pu sretsaor eeffoc euqituob elttil a sah eH
”.uoy tif lliw taht ffuts evah dluohs resserd eht fo reward poT .ti rof oG“
.rood tnorf eht sdrawot ffo gnipmolc
”.ni no emoc ,ydnaM ,olleH“
,top eht fo level eht kcehc ot semit wef a nwod dna pu depmuj
.redluohs reh no dnah yldneirf a tup dna
.nwod ti gnuws ehs yaw eht morf yvaeh dekool tI
.nehctik eht ni yaw eht lla tuo ekam ot maS rof teiuq oot saw taht nruter ni racsO ot gnihtemos dias ydnaM
.mra delcsum eno htiw pu reh kcip racsO tel ehs sa dias maS
.thgin emag ylkeew ruo rof mih ot snaeb etanod I ,waN“
,ecaps dlo reh naht reggib hcum os saw tI
,esoJ naS morf kcab tog ew ecnis derettacs tib a neeb ev’I“
”?snaeb ynam siht ekam ot hguorht gid ot dah I poop hcum woh wonk uoy oD“
”.gnitubirtnoc fo yaw yM
.pu dekool ehs litnu ecaf s’maS ta wap a devaw ydnaM ”?maS ,maS“
?lanrutcon era srevaeb tegrof uoy diD“
.tIdehSohW :yffulF dna eetanaM-elttaB evol I
,gnipeews ot kcab tnew dna daeh reh koohs ydnaM
”.uoy teem ot eciN“
”. . .hu ,hO“ ”?snoitseuq ynA
.rood eht sdrawot yawa gnittort ,werdhtiw neht dna kcab yltneg wap reh dezeeuqs racsO
.reyalp wen a htiw reh desirprus racsO taht ypmurg tsuj s’ehS“
.draobdrac eht revo ydnaM ta evaw dluoc eh os seotpit sih no pu gnidnats ,dias boB
.dekaeuqs ehs ”!tahW“
.noitcerid reh ni decnalg eh no ti denrut d’eh ecnO
.siht od dluoc ehS
”.epoh I ,ylopo-ooZ toN
”.peels nac uoy os teiuq eb ll’eW
.maS fo tnorf ni rehto eht dna ydnaM fo tnorf ni sgum eht fo eno tes racsO
”.em fo gnikniht rof sknaht tub ,flesym ffuts eht knird t’nod I .looc s’ti
,evitceted a sa boj reh ni emit eht lla ti did ehS
”.lerutan ua ti referp I“
ot txen teprac moor gninid eht no reh tes yltneg dna nehctik eht fo tuo kcab deppolc racsO ”.lliw uoy ,seY“
”.yrtnuoc eht ni eeffoc tseb eht sekam boB“
”.uoy ot hcum taht snaem ti fi ,htrow s’ti tahw uoy yap ll’I“
.namuh dna nidalaP tuoba gnihtemos thguac ehS
.maS ot kcab denrut boB dna
.detacilpmoc rehtar saw ti ,tsenoh eb oT
”.esirprus yb em thguac noitcudorp fo dohtem eht sseug I“
.mih ta pu gniralg ,mih no dednuor maS
”!ti taert uoy woh si siht dna ,traeh ym fo ssendoog eht fo tuo syug uoy ot eeffoc ym etanod I“
”.srallod derdnuh neves tsoc dluow spuc ynam taht pohs eeffoc ym tA
.top eht rof dehcaer ynnoR
.teprac eht ot no deppets dna roolf doowdrah eht fo egde eht yb ffo seohs reh koot ehS
”?snamuh tsniaga gnihtemos evah uoY“
”?snaeb eht rof hcum taht yap eh seoD“
”.ynnoR si eman yM“
,erom yas ot tuoba saw eh ekil dekool tI
.retaw fo tekcub gnihsols a htiw moorhtab eht morf degremeer racsO
.maS ot txen taes a gnikat neht dna elbat eht fo retnec eht otno skcans fo yart eht gnidils ,dias racsO
”.thginot uoy gninioj eb ll’I .maS m’I
.dekool ti woh dekil etiuq maS
..nooM ooM elbaffeni eht
.tuo uoy pleh ll’I ,ereH“
.uoy tuoba hcum os em dlot s’racsO“
.pom eht teg og ll’I“ .boB
.lla retfa ,dereffo dah ehS
,reh gninraw tuohtiw retaw poop reh def d’eh eveileb t’ndluoc ehS
.ffuts laiceps si siht
”.lla dna evom eht gninnalp htiw tahw
.sdneirf ruoy fo erom teem ot deticxe m’I ,sediseB
.daer ot reh rof elbissopmi ti gnikam
.srosicni tnorf dezisrevo reh ffo gniwohs ,nirg a htiw maS ta pu dekool dna rehtegot swap tnorf reh depsalc airtun ehT ”.aknirZ ydnaM ,rekrow-oc ym si siht ,maS“
”.tik xof eht evas ot tseuq rieht no meht nioj ll’I .haey ,hU
.netfo os reh no gnikcehc deppots eh dna yrettij ssel dna remlac tlef ehs os ro ruoh na retfa tub
.sdrow s’ydnaM no gnisucof elbuort dah ehs dna nups daeh s’maS
.gnicar saw traeh reh ekil tlef tI
loots eht no t’nsaw ehs hsiw reh edam snaeb eht fo llems yttun ,yhtrae ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.nehctik eht dnuora dna ,moordeb eht otni ,moor gnivil eht dnuora spal wef a delddaw ehs ,hguone tsaf llif ot mees t’ndid ti nehw ,neht dna
.lluf saw top eht ,yllaniF
.gnihctiwt sreksihw reh ,meht hctaw ot denrut dna gnipeews deppots ydnaM
”thgiN emaG“   :yojne esaelP
.ssem eht deyevrus dna sessalg reh detsujda ydnaM
.sepirts fo eerf yltcnitsid saw taht liat gnol a dna ,ruf hsiyarg
.gum eht deitpme tsuj dah ehs taht ees ot das
.ecnarelot a pu tliub t’nevah uoy fi drah uoy tih nac ti ni enieffac ehT
.seveels reh koohs yltneg dna edis eht ot tuo smra reh dleh ynnoR
?htrow sgum dezis raluger thgie ,tahw saw taht
,oot ,eeffoc emos uoy gnirb ll’I .taes a ekat ,oN“
,hctip lamron sti ot kcab eciov reh derewol ehs neht
.suovren erom mih edam evah ot demees esnopser reh
.ydnaM htiw koohs dna wap a tuo dleh maS ”.emaS“
”.flesym puc a htiw od dluoc I“
,dewolleb racsO ”?deneppah tahW“
.tellaw reh dehctulc maS ”,mu
”,emag ot kcab og nac ew os pu denaelc siht teg lla s’tel ,woN“ ”.ecno siht tsuj
,diuqil krad gnillems-suoiciled eht fo lluf-flah ylno saw s’maS
.meht ta gninnirg ,dias ydnaM
.flesreh gniyojne saw maS llits tub
.dehsinif eh nehw tellaw eht deppord tsomla dna depsag ehs tub
.semag draob yas t’ndid I“
”.gnitfilpU eht erofeb seirutnec rof ti gniknird neeb dah snamuH
.gnihton ot dehcatta saw won hcihw
.elims gnirussaer a mih evag dna rehtegot sregnif-devooh sih dezeeuqs ehS
”.ma yllaer I .eeffoc eht tuoba yrros m’I ,boB“
.pmuj boB gnikam ,teprac eht tsniaga liat talf reh deppals ehS ”?maS ,thgir
,yadot ni devom tsuj uoy wonk I“
,regguR .P .B yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
”?saw ti tahw wenk uoy erofeb ti deyojne uoy yas uoy t’ndiD“
.ni deppets dah nidalap s’maS taht part a mrasid ot deirt dah feiht s’boB nehw noisses eht ni reilrae pu emoc dah taht selur eht fo aitunim emos tuoba boB htiw gnivah saw eh noitasrevnoc eht pots t’ndid tub dnuora deirrucs ehs sa secnalg desumeb reh tohs racsO
,dewolleb racsO ”,gnimoC“
,thgir er’uoY“ ”.lacipyT“
”.emoh raew ot stnap dna trihs a worrob ot deen ll’I“
”.noitanigami fo emag A“ .deksa maS
.dnatsrednu t’nod I ,tsuj I ,oN ?tahW“
”.emag eht ot kcab teg nac ew os ylkciuq pu denaelc siht teg nac ew
.gnar llebrood eht tnemom taht ta tub
.pac dialp reh fo pot yzzuf eht saw won reh fo ees dluoc maS lla dna reh fo tnorf ni teehs draobdrac dedlof a pu tes dah ydnaM
.eman eht dezingocer maS .ydnaM
deen I“ .ylduol denway dna dehcterts ynnoR thgindim tuoba tA
.gniretne erew yeht pmaws eht ebircsed ydnaM ot denetsil ehs sa draobpuc eht fo tuo emoc tsuj dah ti fi sa naelc sa dekcil saw gum eht litnu rovalf fo pord tsal yreve gniyojne
”.eeffoc llems I ,racsO“
,stseug sih rof seidoog ekab racsO depleh ehs ,gnikcapnu emos gniod retfA
.hguone t’nsaw gnilialf reH
,ekops eh sa sllib eht hguorht gnibmuht neeb dna tellaw reh tuo dellup dah maS
,em htiw sneg-erp wef a yrrac syawla I ylikcuL
.ten.relleknosidam
,tsuj I ,ytsat yllautca saw tI .yrros m’I
,boB ,mih retal tnemom a dna
.eno erutainim a saw eh fi neve
”.lufrednow sllems ti tuB
.trihs lennalf dialp kcalb-dna-der reh dehctam taht evolg liat tink der thgirb a yb derevoc saw liat niht ,gnol s’airtun ehT
.elacs nehctik sih no puc a otno ti morf snaeb kcalb gniruop nageb dna txen tuo gab cillatem dlog a dellup eh sa yliraw ti deye maS
”?tauosseT ot dnopser nidalap ruoy seod woh ,maS ,oS“
,ti fo edisni eht dekcil dna puc eeffoc ytpme reh pu dekcip dna tuo decaps ehS
.sgum s’enoyreve detcelloc dna pu doots ynnoR
”.motsuc gnihtemos uoy edam evah dluoc I“
,noitnetta reh desucofer dna eeffoc eht fo pis rehtona koot maS
.renroc eht dnuora deraeppasid racsO
.nehctik eht otni deppiks tsomla dna dennirg racsO ”.top hserF“
.elims a reh dehsalf racsO
.noitciF degnaF yb
”.boB ,erutuf eht ni eeffoc ruoy fo luftcepser erom eb ll’I esimorp I .racsO ,thgir s’tahT“
.resolc tib a nael ot seot debbew reh fo spit eht no doots ehS
.ruf s’maS morf ssalg hsurb yltneg ot desu eh hcihw
”.doog siht dellems reven yeht tub ,tsap eht ni spohs eeffoc tsap deklaw ev’I
si koob tsewen esohw dna
,edur neeb evah dluow ti
.draobdrac eht dnuora ydnaM ta kool ot edis eht ot denael dna serutcip eht ta denworf maS
”.ni meht tel I elihw retcarahc ruoy ta kool a ekaT“
.nwod kcab tas maS sa deffuh ydnaM
”.tnedicca na saw tI .kaerb a maS tuc ,boB ,nom’C“
.retawrednu flah neeb dah egdol reh taht tcaf eht noitnem ot toN
.enihcam gnikool-detacilpmoc eht otni tsud naeb eht deruop dna gurhs a htiw dias eh ”,eeffoC“
”.keew txen uoy rof ti evah ll’I .yrros m’I
.reh tuoba gniklat syawla saw racsO
.reh ta gniknilb ,pu dekool maS
.tsehc sih ssorca smra sih gnissorc ,maS ta deralg dna deffuh boB
.nuf sdnuos thgin emag dnA
tik gnissim eht dnif ot rehtegot gnikrow erew sretcarahc riehT
.ffo welf ssalg nekorb dna eeffoC
.edam si eeffoc kawuL ipoK woh s’tahT .haey ,lleW“
.swap reh gnola gnicnad erif htiw ebor der gnol a ni desserd nexiv a dna ,drows a gnidleiw nam aneyh a
.reh ot emag eht fo scisab eht denialpxe ydnaM
”.doog yllaer s’ti ,seY“
,dias racsO neht dna ,gninepo rood a fo kaerc eht saw erehT
.deffins dna ydnaM ta redluohs sih revo eralg a tohs boB
.sih saw tnemtrapa ehT .rentrap dna
.puc rehtona gnivarc llits saw ehs terces sti gniwonk etipseD
.woble reh no gnidnal ,edis reh no roolf eht tih ehS