woh tuoba smeop eticer dna
,tilc reh tsniaga ylmrif desserp saw eson siH
?nisiar laemtaO“
”?elbixelF ?tahW“ ”—er’uoy tsael tA
”?I t’nod ,srentrap fo eciohc ym ni nepo mees ylniatrec I .ym hO“
.eganam ot swollaws wef a reh koot ti taht seslup gnorts ni esaeler pu-tnep sih gnitrups
…moor eht dellif lwoh dehctip-hgih reH
,flesmih ot timda ot dah eh ,ton saw eH
.mih hguorht ylbaroxeni daerps ot gnitrats erusaelp eht gnileef
.resolc ti llup ot elbat eht ssorca dehcaer retemeD
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.sehtolc ruoy ffo ekaT“
,ecov ottos ,dedda eh ”,hctib uoY“
nmaD“ ”.retskcirt a kcirt ot yrt reven ,lleW“
,noissap fo seorht eht ni ,taht erus ekam ot sdrawnwod ecnalg a gnidrazah
;elppin reh dehsurb sregnif siH
!em eb dluoc tahT“
,stih fo snoilliM
strups gninekaew eht htiw gnikcub llits ,detnurg eH
hkna sih ekorts kcuf ome taht ot gninetsil setunim ytnewt dneps ot tnaw I kniht uoY“
”?tahw ro ,teb eht esol uoy diD“
,lufniap eb ot sa kciht os ton—
?ekil dnuos smaercs s’xof a tahw wonk uoy oD ?em gnirehtoB“
,rewol swap sih dils dna
;draobyek eht htiw tpeda erom saw ehS
,mih gnitciped segami fo selit ta gnirats
gnikool I ma tahW“ ”.erehT“
?retupmoc ruoy s’erehW“
,delbmum eh ”?tahw nalP“
depsag okikusT ”!kcuf ,hO“
,ylision spohc reh dekcil enustik ehT
ti fo tsom dekcolb erugif evissam A
”.ereh ,naM fo ega eht sdne taht elttab citcamilc eht erofeb peels lanrete elttil a teg ot gniyrt era su fo emoS ?kcuf eht tahw—owt uoY
.reh otni ylhtooms dehsup eh
”,nekat enoN“ ”.esneffo oN“
.eugnot gnol sih dewollaws ylraen eh
sdlrow-htiw-rereknit lareneg dna
”?neppah taht did nehW ?taht s’tahw—
”?setoyoc tsuJ“ .dekrims okikusT
”…draugnav ruo eb ll’yeht tub ,tey ti wonk t’nod yehT
,yldas daeh reh gnikahS ”.raed ,hO“
.yawa llef klis eht gurhs diulf eno htiw dna
”.wonk uoy ,oot ,tonk a tog s’eH“
.ebyam ,sraeY ?shtnoM
eman sih
”,straeh erom oN“ ”?emag rehtonA
.eslup gniwollof hcae ot emit ni
.pu ti gninepo dna
”.rohT ,traeh taht htiw od ot gniog m’I tahw wonk t’nod I“
.tiderc ekat ot gnilliw naht erom saw eh tub—
kcoc gnislup ,toh s’eninac eht dnuora gnihcterts
,me‘ htiw ffo woN
”.lepahC enitsiS eht s’ti ,meht fo nward tra naf teg sdog emos nehw ,wonk uoY
…fo dnik uoy neht tuB
.dnilbroloc saw eno nehw
”’.krowtra tneceR‘ ?ta
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,mih teem ot kcab reh gnillup
,romra eht tuohtiw neve—
.deit er’uoy nehw ti hcaer t’nac eh taht ratiug citsuoca sih morf yawa hguone raf tub—sih ta ro
”…retteb s’taht ,erehT ?ees ,hO“
”?…esuaceb wonk d’uoy dnA“ .desiar sworbeye
.dennirg enustik ehT
.ycneced fo stimil emos detcepser etoyoC neve
,yltneg reh gnidaenk—
“ neercs eht sdrawot elzzum reh detlit ehs ”—ll’I ro
.ylgnivorppa tsehc erab sih revo derednaw seye esohw
su teg nac I ,dias I
.desaet gnieb rof doom eht ni ton saw eh taht dediced eh dna
.mih evoba ssenkrad eht otni emit a rof dereep eh ,kcab sih nO
tsurht gniwollof hcae sa
,reh edisni eugnot sih deppils etoyoC
.ydob gnireviuq reh edisni peed dils tfahs s’etoyoc eht sa
,elzzum mraw reh ni drah emac eh sa ylmrif delkcus dna
.srae eht yb mih dezies neht dna
.eugnot reh dekcilc ehs dna
,delworg ehS ”?yhW
,era yeht tahw gnieb stner ,tub
,rekampam ,retirw a si ohw
,sresuort mined yvaeh sih denetsafnu eh
xes reh fo spil knip ,tfos eht gnicaf flesmih dnuof dna
,draeh eh eerf teg ot delggurts eh elihw dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,deb eht otni nwod delttes etoyoC
eveileb srewollof ruoY“
,reh otni dehsug eh sa deredduhs ikusT
.gniylf sdrac gnidnes ,elbat eht otni dehsams tsif siH ”?nisiar laemtaO
dexaler ehs emit eht yb noisiv sih ni stops krad erew erehT
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.kcoc deirub sih fo sehctiwt eltneg wef a
”?seikooc pihc etalocohc edam uoY“
”.etisbew ylno eht t’nsi sihT
.yek ’retne‘ eht tih dna
.ecalp ni lwocs sih peek ot deirt eh
.deffuh eH ”?reggib ,wonk uoy
,derob erew uoy taht dias uoY“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,driaB boR yb
.dees etoyoc mraw htiw reh gnillif
,siht hsilpmocca ot pu dnats ot dah eH
;thgie eht deyalp retemeD
ruf etihw tfos hguorht sregnif ynwat desserp taht ezeeuqs gniregnil a tsaerb s’xof eht gnivig
,kciuq ni reh gnittur
.eugnot sih fo sekorts eht dniheb erusserp fo tib a dda ot nwod gniwols
.od ot sgniht evah ot demees syawla ohw
.sreksihw reh gnilppad llits etoyoc fo spord eht yb devres-llew ylralucitrap ton saw taht tceffe na
…repeed gnidoolf
”.won kcab daor eht no er’eW
sdrac eht pu depoocs xof eht
ecalp gnillewd sih si ecaps peeD
.god.gnitirw no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,ynamreG ,nilreB ni talf a speek eh
,naorg teiuq a htiw ,nehT
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.dniheb etalp eht gnivael
,derevaw srae s’okikusT ”…wA“
.riahc sih ni kcab denael dna ,dias etoyoC
.gnisopmi dna delcsum saw eh
.kcaj eht htiw deyalprednu
,tliub taeh ykcits eht
,ylgnigilbo denaom ehs dna
.straeh fo net eht ni dessot dna ,decamirg rohT
,ecno ta owt htiw toN
.ffo naelc rebmem sih kcus ot deganam ton dah elzzum delliks reh
.reh morf pils thgim ti ecnahc on saw ereht taht ylthgit os
,raer s’enustik eht otni denael eh dna
.naom-flah tfos a tuo tel ehs
deganam eh yllanif tub ,eciwt ro ecno ruf eht dehcnip eh sa denihw ehs dna ,tluciffid
.yltneg htaehs sih gnikorts sregnif tfos reh tlef eh dna
.hctorc sih fo ruf eht otni degdun eson dloc reh ,edisni yaw eht lla mih koot ehs nehw
.enustik eht morf htao gnipley rehtona gniward
.yltnalutep rehtar dna
,setunim gninevretni eht ni
.ylgnivorppa delworg okikusT dna—htaehs sih morf gnippils kcoc s’etoyoc eht fo hself kcils ,erab eht—
devorp sliat reh neewteb deb eht ot gnitteG
”,ereht gnikat er’uoy stniop fo toL“
”.yppup ,ecin yalp :nom’C“
.ylirgnuh mih ta dekcus okikusT sa gnillol eugnot sih
”?won yppah uoy erA“
,lla retfa ,saw eh—
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.etoyoC ta ti gnilggaw ,regnif a desiar eH
”,pot eht revo em stup taht eveileb I“
”?ikusT ,selcatnet evah tnalp taht seoD
,mih dnuora tew dna mraw os saw ehS
”?htiw teb taht edam uoy nosrep ylno eht I saW .em llet oS“
”?rood eht esolc ot gniog uoy fo rehtie erew nalp eht ni tniop tahw tA“ “-- ot nalp ot uoy rof dennalp I …I
.edisni serugif owt htiw
enustik eht dnuora smra gnol sih gnipparW
…yaw emos ni pu mih pirt ot neek os ,gnidnamed os—
.mih tsniaga reh gnillup
.mih erofeb seenk reh ot deppord neht dna
.tik ,enoyreve rof emit yzarc a erew seitxis ehT“
.flesmih ot
.tnemtrapa sih ot ecnartne eht ecaf ot dnuora nups eh sa
etaciled ylralucitrap ton saw tI
.kcab dekcilf srae s’etoyoC
,mih ta erats ot ylprahs ydob reppu reh detsiwt ehS
.moor eht ssorca dellac eh ”!auhsoJ
,erusaelp fo lrans a htiw
,ylteews delims enustik ehT
”.siht ta kool ,ereH“
”…tub ,enod evah thgim I“
.woble na no pu flesreh depporp okikusT
taebtraeh hcae htiw neffits ot gnitrats saw eH
,tib a spih reh delggiw ehS
,okikusT esaelp ot demees sihT
.sregnif ynob gniyalps
,potpal sih barg ot revo denael enustik ehT .gniworran seye
,reh ot kcab draobyek eht denrut etoyoC
”.taht ekil gnihtyna htiw laed ot ysub oot eb ll’eW
:esruoc fo ,egral taht ton saw tI
,ton dah s’etoyoC taht etartsnomed ot
”?sibunA htiw gnorw s’tahW“
.dehcra kcab reh sa
,ylguns os mih gnizeeuqs
.swap reh pu dessot okikusT ”?tahw oS“ ”…oS“
,tfahs sih no dexif erew seye ediw reH
.tsehc s’etoyoc eht otni kcab denael dna
.kcab tnew srae sih dna ,deknilb eh nehT
,mih dleh dna raer sih ta swap reh tup okikusT
,spil reh dnuora morf ti decrof
,etihw ymaerc a saw tlep s’enustik ehT
,tfahs sih fo pit eht delkcus ehS
.delggig enustik ehT
ezis lluf ot dellews dah hcihw
”.ikusT ,swap ruoy no teG
”?yllaeR ?ti s’taht oS“
.ylleb reh ta detser yeht litnu
”.thguoht I naht revarb er’uoY“ .deksa okikusT
.wap sih htiw ylhguor pih reh degdun eh
.repmihw t’nod tsael ta tub ,enif ,llew yllanif dna setunim elpuoc a rof tuo dloh ,naem I tub ,ti ta doog yllaer s’ehs sselnu
,tsehc reh revo smra reh dessorc okikusT ”.fo troS“
,srae s’enustik eht ta deppirg swap siH
degdew tonk sih dnuof eh litnu lawardhtiw hcae gnitset
.ilthcopoliztiuH iH .hO“
.sessalg deroloc-esor htiw tsap eht no kool ot ton tseb saw ti
,delworg eh ”,yllautcA“
.etalp a gnireffo ,elbat eht revo tneb erugif wen A
meht deppilF“ .dedda ehs ”,meht eta eh nehT“ ”?did eH“ .desserpmi dekool rohT  ”.efil ot peehs eht thguorb eh ,emit tsaL“ .niaga gnitrats ,dewollaws ehS ”.yrros—mhtsmL“ .eikooc fo lufhtuom a dnuora pu ekops retemeD ”?tahW“
.enotonom krad ,lufelab a ni yrteop kcom eht daer ehS
.meht neewteb delttes dna
.seenk reh no pu reh gniward ,revo reh deppilf dna
.elpoep evitpecer niatrec fo smaerd eht ot tuo gnihcaer neeb ev’I
”.taht od ot em …rof nalp ot uoy rof dennalp I .haeY“
gnah ecnelis eht tel dna
.dnuos eht htiw mih revo gnihsur htaerb toh
.tnemeriter fo seirutnec sih rof epahs roop ylbirret ni
.dias ehs ”,era erehT“
,elbatrofmocnu mih edam
”.thguoht evah thgim uoy sa eid ot yaw a tnasaelp sa“ ,dias yllanif eh
drawrof spih sih gnidnirg
.yldipar debbe rewoplliw siH
?selcatnet esoht erA ?tnalp a taht si
.deppots dah strups eht litnu
.lworg detcartsid ,gnirevaw a htiw derewsna ehs
”?rood eht esolc uoy naC“
,fo tib a tuoba suoiruc ton er’uoY“
”.teb a no tcelloc ot“ ,dias ehs
.retskcirt-wollef ,uoy neve ebyaM
.seot sih ni sresuort sih gnizies ,sgel sih fo eno tuo dehcterts eH
,syek eht no gnitser swalc
.yltnatcepxe enustik eht ta dekool
.rettam t’now ti hguone nooS“
reh dniheb ylizal gnivaw sliat—
:uoy gnillet m’I tuB .yrutnec htneetruof eht oslA
.deffocs etoyoc ynit eht ”,t’nac uoy teb I“
ecnalbmeser gnikirts a raeb ot ,ylesolc dereep etoyoC taht won ,deraeppa ohw—rehto eht ot dias eno ”,sreppihsrow dnasuoht net su teg nac I“
.kaolc yzzuf a ekil meht neewteb sliat reh dna
:esruoc fo ,thgir saw ehS
”gnuremmädrettöG ta semaG“
reh morf decrof neeb dah drow eht ekil
.ylprahs tuo deirc enustik eht litnu ,stnemevom rekciuq ni ,gniog tpek eH
.efilretfa evitinup ylhgih ,deurtsnoc ylevitagen s’ydobyna ni ecnahc a toN“
…ot detoved mees ylniatrec yehT“
.reh gninioj ,denoituac eh ”,ecno siht tsuJ“
”.drow eno lla s’tI .ecaps on s’ereht ,on ,oN ?tahw—ruF .ten
,sliat hguone evah t’nseod ti ,naem I
,mih ta gnippirg dna gnimsaps sllaw
”.niaga srewollof detnaw dna
driaB boR yb ”gnuremmädrettöG ta semaG“:yojne esaelP
”.erus m’I ,desirprus eb ll’yehT“
.yawyna ,gnineve eht rof eriter dluohs eh taht dewolla dna pu evag etoyoC
;reh dniheb digir dna
?tahW“ .deknilb etoyoC
.eugnot reh gninaelc
.gniyas m’I lla s’tahT .ybboh a s’ti nehw tnereffid …s’tI“ .denworf etoyoC
.hctorc sih ta wap etihw-nottoc a devaw ehs
emaceb tsaf oot emoc t’noD
;rovaf sih ni gnikrow saw teg ot drah gniyalp taht noicipsus gnikaens eht dah etoyoC ”…lleW“
,ecalp ruoy ta rehtie ti od uoy taht erus ekam ot evah tsuj uoy ,yako s’eh
.htaerb rof gnitnap ,delggig okikusT
”?devlovni teg ot evah sucif eht oD
;ffurg saw eciov s’rohT
.edis thgirb eht no kool tub—haey ,seniV“
;ezis lluf ta won—
retal sdnoces wef a
;erus eb ot ,erofeb neeb dah eh naht regral saw ti tuB
.ti gnikat eb ll’uoy eveileb I“
.semag suoregnad era ereht neht dna ,semag suoregnaD“
.retteb saw taht ,seY
”?kram noitseuq a raeh uoy diD“
:peek ot deganam eh ,tsael ta ,sihT
,hctorc reh otni deson dna
…srotplucs ,sretirw ,stsitrA
.nward evah elpoep taht krowtra tneceR“
”,ton s’tahT“ ”?yako uoy erA“
”…t’nsaw ti uoy rof ton ebyaM“
,daeh sih fo edis rehtie ot depmalc shgiht reh erofeb
”?drazah emos rof ni uoY“
”.doohnam ym gnitlusni ot enorp ssel er’yehT“
a ton m’I dnA“ .dias etoyoC
.kcats taen a ni meht tes dna
,mih gnilffur htaerb mraw tlef etoyoC retal tnemom A
,esle gnihtyna yas t’ndid eH ”.ebyaM“
.gnihtemos gnikil ni sa ’,ytiniffa‘ dna
,enod eb ot gnihton saw ereht hcihw tuoba
suomehpsalb neeb ev’thgim taht noitatrohxe na gnidda
”.gnisufnoc s’taht fi ,esoppus I ,ralimis era srettel eht—dog a m’I .god
”,fo troS .llew …rO !su fO
,emit a ta eno meht morf sgel sih gnillup
.yas ,em regnuoy a …tub
”…taht llacer …t’nod I“ ”.t’nac
?tahw roF“ .stnap sih ta teg ot gniyrt
,nepo ot ti gniddib ,sregnif sih deppans eh
.ti dniheb ecilam on saw ereht hguohtla
:slavretni feirb ni ylno nekorb
.daeh sih koohs eH
,evah I dna uoy tahw ni sa
.dehguoc okikusT ”,yrroS“
,sesoprup dna stnetni lla rof
.ylhguor yawa meht dettaws okikusT
.dehsinav noitirappa eht dna
.tibmag reh fo tnemele emos dessim ,spahrep ,dah eh hguoht sa ,mih derehtob gnisarhp reh tuoba gnihtemoS
.seninac owt eht neewteb gnikool
.repsihw deifirroh a ni ffo deliart sseddog eht ”…smaercs ehT
’daed eht fo dnal eht ni sselemoh lla era ew‘
.kool ytliug ylthgils a htiw
.kcirt eht detcelloc dna—
,segelivirp emos evah ot dah
.ylthgit reh degguh eH ”?haeY“
”,uoy ot gnimoc s’tahw teg ot tuobA“
.worbeye na detfil etoyoC
ti raeh ot elba saw eh dnoces eht rof
.okikusT derevocsid dna
.enustik eht ot worbeye na gnisiar
”?’enim dehgiew sah enoyreve ekil luos ruoy hgiew lliw I‘ dna
,sreh ot dehsalc spih sih sa yltnegru erom reh deppirg eh
”…ruoy demeeder tsomla ev’uoy ebyaM“ .etib a koot dna
”?tnaw uoy od tahW“
.seenk sih ot gnitteg dna lleps kciuq a gnitsac ,derettum etoyoC
,guh a reh gnivig dna
.dda t’ndid eh ,su gnoma rewols eht roF
,enustik eht ta derewolg etoyoC ”.oot stnaP“
.esle enoyna ot sa
,rehtaf sih dna auhsoJ ekil srewollof dah eh hcihw ni syad eht dessim eh semitemoS
.ylesolc erutcip eht gninimaxe ,kcab retupmoc sih koot eH ”?thgiR
.repmihw laref yllacitsiretcarahcnu na evag ehs dna
elkna sih raen elzzum reh deppans ehS ”—erew teb eht fo smret eht thguoht I
.pord yreve rof mih gniklim
,flesmih thguac neht dna
”…m’I ,dnah rehto eht no ,eM“
.stniop eerht-ytnewT
”…dna ,tib a rof setoyoc-ydal ytterp tuoba kniht …I .nac I“
,ylregae sdlof reh gnola ti gnidils
.ydob gnimsaps reh tsniaga deppart flesmih dnuof eh dna
!erom s’ereht dnA“
.reh erofeb doots tahw ot neercs eht no egami na gnirapmoc ,pu ti dleh dna
”.yllaer ,deb ni dab taht lla ton yllautca s’eH“
.ydob reh fo ecnatsiser eht tsap hsup ot
”?ti fo tahW .did I ebyam os ,thgirlA“ .ekorb eh taht elbatrofmocnu os saw eh tsal ta litnu
.teb a rebmemer t’nod I ?teB“
”?uoy gnirehtob …ew ereW
.snaom teiuq reh leef dluoc etoyoC taht mih ot ylthgit os gnignilc ,detnap ehS
”?seikooc stnaw ohW“
,yltneconni dias ehs ”,hO“ ”?gnol woH“
,deworruf worb s’okikusT ”…eY“
.osrot nael sih ffo ti gniggurhs dna
,okikusT ta elbat eht ssorca deralg rohT
,thguoht etoyoC ,dog a gnieB .emos neht dna—
”?gnihtemos ro esroh a ,ekil ,dnif ot gniog uoy erA“
.yltneconni net eht deppord ehS
.ecalp otni flesmih ediug ot rehto eht gnisu ,wap eno htiw yawa sliat eht tpews eH
,rrup a ni dias saw siht ”…etoyoC ,nom’C“
yldrawkwa ,denrut etoyoC
.ezeeuqs mrif a ni mih deppirg enustik eht sa
,god a ekil detnap eH
,tnemrag nikskcub eht didnu ylwols etoyoc eht ,hgis rehtona htiW ”.god ,no emoC
.pil sih no dewehc god tresed eht ,gninworF
niaga ti did eh nehw dna
.sretsop pu gnitnirp trats—
”?taht od uoy t’noD“
”?revo ti saw tahW
suonosiop si etalocohc esuaceb ,hguoht ,seippup eht rof ton—
.eugnot tevlev s’okikusT fo sekorts tfos eht neht dna
,ylhguor pmur reh ta debbarg etoyoC
,lrans gnilbbub a ni kcab nward saw elzzum siH
”.trats doog a si shtnom enin yas d’I“
bmow reh demialc demialc eh sa dna
,rehtegot swap reh deppalc okikusT
.stimil yrev ot reh gnisserp tub
.deb eht otno gnicnuop ,doots dna
mih ot emas eht dekool enustik eht
,onomik dlog a ni ,etihw eruP
.tfel sdnomaid tub gnihton dah eh
,tius eht ni tfel gnihtyna htiw eno ylno eht eb ot gnivorp ,etoyoC
,eson sih delkcit ruf tfos ehT
”.taht …otni em dedaog
,reh morf pils mih tel ehs nehT
”?sibunA htiw gnipeels fo ksir eht nur annog m’I kniht uoY
,muc sih fo trups gnorts tsrif eht htiw ylidaeh denaorg eh
,delbmurg etoyoC ”,sreltteS yalp ot dewolla ton m’I“
.yrd eciov sih gnipeek
skrej gnihctih ,trohs
,yldetsugsid daeh sih koohs nam llat ehT
”?naem ot desoppus taht s’tahW“ .depoord srae siH
,pu yaw eht lla mottob eht morf gnicart
,smra gnol sih tuo dehcterts etoyoC
,eman sih dellac ehs dna
.nik dliw rieht fo yteltbus eht lla htiw enustik eht gnikcuf
:ecitcarp fo tuo ,spahrep ,ylereM .orp a
,onomik reh gniytnu ,doots ehS
.yllufeelg rehtegot swap reh debbur tirips-xof ehT
,sregnif sih fo sdap eht htiw hself ffits eht gnilcric
.edis sih sserac wap s’enustik eht tlef eh dna ,desaet ehs
detrap sgel reh htiw
,deraeppa llab etihw gniwolg a ,meht neewteB
,toof sih htiw yltneg reh devohs eH ”?kcab uoy yaP“
.htuom s’enustik eht fo foor eht revo gnidilg tfahs sih fo pit eht gnileef
.emit fo rettam a tsuj s’ti tuB .won rof ,daetsni
.rettam t’ndid siht
,ylgnisucca delworg xof etihw ehT
”?rebmemeR“ .seye sih detreva dna
deggurhs ylpmis ,xof etihw eht ,okikusT tuB
shgiht reh fo ruf eht otni kaos ot seciuj nwo s’namow-xof eht htiw gnixim
reh ydaets ot pu wap a tup eh nehw dna ,dekcub spih reH
esnet tnew etoyoC
.niaga dias eh ”,ebyaM“
.yltfos delggig ehS
…ti ekam dluoc uoy hsiw reve uoy t’noD“
,taps rohT ”,god tahT“
.trapa swap reh daerps ehS
,reh dellif eh emit hcae denaorg ehS .stsurht lufrewop
.hsur citnarf ,lanif a ni tih esaeleR
,tonk sih yb depparT
,erusopmoc sti fo elttil a tsol ecaf s’okikusT
”,sgnileef ruoy truh ot naem t’ndid I“
.desirprus eb ot gniog era elpoep fo stoL .llew ,hA“
dnatsthgin eht morf potpal sih gnillup ,dehgis etoyoC
”.emag suoregnad a gniyalp er’uoY“
.sdnomaid fo owt eht deyalp dna
”?uoy rof gnitiaw si sedaps fo neeuq eht knihT“ .delworg eh
,kcen reh morf gnuh taht tnadnep a yb
seye gnicreip htiw ,emosdnah ,gnuoy—nam ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,dna resworb a detrats eh tub
,tsetorp t’ndid ehs ,gnidnatshtiwton siht tuoba wonk etiuq t’nod ,dnA
?won enod ew era oS“
.os dias I esuaceB“
.gnilbmert llits ,deganam ehs ”,yrros ,hO“
,deb sih no nwod retupmoc eht gnitteS
,gnilkcac llits ,ffo detnirps eh nehT
’tahw teg ot tuobA’“ ”.eveileb I“
troffe erom dna erom koot taht tonk gnillews eht dna
:rood sih ta kconk a saw erehT
.noisiv sih ssorca dleifrats a tniap ot wap a devaw eh dna
”?meht ot lepsog ruo gnitacinummoc tuoba od ot gniog uoy era tahW
,esirprus ni dekrab eh—
,thgiled htiw gnimriuqS
.htaeneb hself gnidleiy eht ot
,emit dnoces a siht detaeper eh oS
.denaorg etoyoC dna
.segami esoht yb gnigduj ,reyarp ni ton
.detcerroc okikusT
.dnomaid tsewol sih deyalp dna
.snoitautis evitacovorp ylgnisaercni ni ,ylgnivol fi
.dewollof taht hcnup eht morf yawa dekcud dna
,flesmih ot dettimda etoyoC ,ylralucitraP
htgnel digir sih revo detrad dna dekcilf eugnot tew ,tfos reH
,’e‘ rettel eht ni sa ,E .taht eganam nac uoy neve kniht I .srettel ruof ylno s’eno siht ,spmarg ,oN“ .daeh reh koohs ehs tub
.ylirgna deraor eh ,gnihsalf seyE
”.sevlesmeht kcil dna ,slamina rehto esahc dna
,llew …ni detseretni mees t’nod yeht hguohtla ,tseretni emos ekots ot deganam evah uoy esoppus I ,thgirlA
”gnuremmädrettöG ta semaG“ saw sihT
”?dad ruoy tuoba tahW“
.nworf thgils a htiw sgel sih neewteb gnirats
.uoy fo erutcip gnisimorpmoc a ekat ot gniog tsuj ebyam saw I“
.elzzum sih fo tnorf ni naf a ekil sliat reh gnivaw
sliat reh ;desucofnu og ot gnitrats erew seye siH
,ti morf gnilruc llits saw maets eht mraw os ,eno debbarg rohT ”.derob tog I“
.erus ton m’I“ .detnurg etoyoC
lortnoc ni flesmih peek ot noiton tnasaelpnu eht desu dna
mih ot resolc deppets ehs sa dna
.elzzum reh dekcil etoyoC
,sgniht gnitsugsid tae yeht dna ,lanrac era sgoD“
.htaerb sih hctac ot thguof eh sa gnikrow tsehc sih
,deohce eh ”?’huH’“ ”.huH“
.nrocpop ekiL .wam sih—sih otni
”.ti gnikat eb ll’uoy eveileb I ,yllautcA“
:gnihton ot ffo derepat yllanif dah ti litnu
niaga liaw okikusT ,ylmid
.tniop doog a s’tahT“ .detnurg rohT
…htiw ton ylniatrec dna
,emoh tresed gnilwarps sih ekilnu os ,secaps desolC
,enustik ylepahs eht fo thgis eht yb denedrub hguoht sa daeh sih gnikahs
.srab rewol ylevissergorp gnittes saw etoyoC ,trap sih roF
,semit wef a retemeD dna etoyoC neewteb decnalg rohT
,dnah sih ta dekool etoyoC
”…esruoc fo ,srewollof lufhtiaf ruoy roF ?tnemtcane-er …hu
?drazaH“ .revo dessorc—
.ssenregae reh deggaw yeht sa rulb a gnimoceb erew
.resolc deddap dna
.neeb dah ti gnol woh niatrec t’nsaw eH
.t’nac uoy teb I ,dias uoy dnA
,dennirg ehs ”,tey toN“
”.emit ti evig tsuJ
.deggurhs ikoL  .deksa rohT
.ruf kciht hguorht gnikop
.spih sih no sdnah sih htiw okikusT decaf eh enod saw ti nehw dna
nwod gnikcab fo sngis yna wohs t’ndid ehs nehw tub
.noitseuq ni dog eht ton eh erew
,sdnomaid fo neeuq eht eb ot tuo denrut od ot gniog m’I tahW
”?sreltteS rof enoynA“
.neercs eht ssorca detniap saw
sgel gnol s’namow-xof eht revo ylluferac flesmih gnuws eh sa ereht wap sih gnivael
,yltnalahcnon deggurhs eH ”!ti
,lliswodniw sih erofeb ecaps eht detanimod taht stnalp eht ta revo dekool eH
’snaf‘ htiw og s’teL“
.gniggurhs ,dehguoc etoyoC
”.kcab em yap uoy litnu toN
.smeop sih naht esrow era sgnos siH
,reh ta gnippal saw eh litnu ecap eht pu gnikcip ,driht a dna
,tuo denrut ti sA
,ylesolc spih reh degguh eH
,yliraew dehgis eH
ylmrif spih reh dezies eH
selppin reh fo knip tfos eht dna
.pmad ylthgils ydaerla—
nevo eht morf hserF“
,lwoh a tuo tel enustik eht
,troffe emos koot ti gnitalupinaM
”,ereh m’I“ ”?uoy pleh I naC“
daeha owt ro pets a naht erom gnikniht ta doog ylralucitrap ton saw etoyoC ,ytilaer nI
ydob elitref eht otni peed muc sih depmup eh sa
.saedi yna teg t’noD“
,yawyna ,emit sih koot eh dnA
,sseddog gnirevihs eht fo
,denialpxe ehs ”,etirovaf yM“
”!ruc sselronoh uoY“
.retrofmoc a ekil mih dnuora sliat reh depparw okikusT dna
,elttil a kcub ot detrats etoyoC
.rae dekrep reh ta delbbin etoyoC
,mih ta deralg okikusT
”.neppah ot dab gnihtyna tnaw t’ndluow I dna
emoselbuort os neeb dah yeht tuB
…em …uoy rof nalp ot uoy rof dennalp I …I .oN“
.semag suoiverp rieht fo htob now osla dah ohw
”.ecid yalp t’nseod daD .syug ,yrroS .haN“
tod ytiniffa ruF
.elbatirahc naht ssel mih tfel dah noitaixyhpsa htiw hsurb eht dna
”’.evilA ’niyatS‘ ekil kool ’nitaS etihW ni sthgiN‘ sekam eh raews I
”.dnik taht ton s’tI
.sseug I ,htrow s’ti tahw roF“
.tsenoh uoy peek ot enoemos deen d’eW
,meht revo eugnot sih dekrow eH
.eb ot ton dedneterp yllareneg eh god eht ekil
mih dnuora spil reh desolc ehS
,daeh s’etoyoc eht no wap a detser ehs
, ,driaB boR ecalperiF eht fo dneirF yb
llew detaluclac d’eH
.ti kaerb dluow rehtien raelc saw ti litnu
,tnemeerga yna ot emoc ot elba t’nerew yehT
,tfahs sih fo pit eht morf yllarebil dellips mucerP
.flesreh ksat eht dehsinif dna retupmoc eht dezies ehs litnu ,emit a ta eno srettel eht tuo gnikcep ,niaga deirt eH
,pu spih sih dehcra eh dna ,desnet sgel sih
,ylprahs dekcub neht dna
,reh depmuh eh sa sehcnuah reh otni gud swalc siH
”.yad elgnis yreve
,neercs eht deppat eH ”.sey
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.ylivaeh dehgis dog dlo eht
.taht enod reve ev’I kniht t’nod I ,lleW“
”?sretskcirt fo riap a htiw ecnahc fo emag A“ ”?drazaH .thgiR“
”?delttes s’teb ehT
ylpeed os htaerb rof gnipsag ,yawa dellup eh dna
.sreppihsrow dnasuoht net
,detlih flesmih gnipeek
,ylsuoiraorpu dehgual ikoL
?ot enog evah I dluow esle ohW“
,pu ti tpek eh oS
”…siht tuoba wonk …etiuq t’nod I“
;retemeD morf eno ,won ,dna rohT morf traeh rehtona reh detten hcihw
ni depyt ylluferac eh ,deuqip ytinaV ”.taht rof hcraeS ’.etoyoC‘ .hu …rof hcraeS .gnihtemos rof hcraeS“ ”?tahw woN .thgirlA“ .daol ot egap eht rof detiaw dna ,ylwols ,depyt eH ”.ten toD .eno-ytnewt dna derdnuh xis neht dna
,seye rebma gnilloR
’,ruF‘ .ten tod ytiniffaruf ot oG .yakO“ ”?seY“
,detrons ikusT ”?oS“  .deraeppasid
.krims hsilived a reh evag dna
”?wonk uoy ,kcolf yM
ylluferac ti gninottubnu
”?em eraps dluoc yeht sdnomaid yna evah ydobyna seoD
.3002 ecnis tfarc sih ta neeb sah ohw
.toofa saw tahw wenk lla yeht
”?taht nalp uoy diD“
;debbe xamilc sih fo sevaw eht sa
flesreh ekil enustik a fo egami deliated ylsuolucitem eht
.derekcins ikusT ”,lleW“
noissucsid sseltiurf fo etunim a retfa dna
.emos su teg dluoc I dias I dnA“
.ot dnetta ot sgniht emos tog ev’I ,oN
,yltnetni mih ta derats ehS
.srewollof eseht tuoba oS .thgiR“
,mih denimaxe ehs sa gnisrup spil
”.tenretnI eht no oG
.emit a ta pets enO“
si yrots s’yadot dna
.ylkaew mih dlot ehs ”,taht od ot uoy rof dennalp I …I“
,modgnik lamina eht fo tsom htiw sdneirf er’uoy taht
.taht fo thguoht ydaerlA“
mih htiw nwod ikusT gnillup—
.tekcaj sih ta deggut dna
.kcab flesmih dloh ot drah saw ti taht
?ereh etisbew sihT
:elttil a depmuh spih siH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.niaga denaom okikusT dna
.nworf tneconni na no tup ehs
”?sreppihsrow yb nward erew esehT .strap niatrec
sehcni wef a kcab dellup eH
.tuhs ti demmals dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT