".nam ,sllirht elttil eht s'tI
.mih depmuj etag eht elihw no saw evird eht fi
!aH"  .hgual a tuo dekrab dna ksed sih deppals xirB
,smmoc tsom rof ti deen t'ndid yehT
,knil eht fo dne rehto eht tA
.ssorC nrehtuoS eht sa nwonk senal edart fo riap a fo ecneulfnoc eht ta tas flesti hcihw
.pmuj ot sdnoces neT"
.taht ekil saw eH
,rehtegot swap sih debbur neR
.eixirB ,yaw ruoy ti evaH"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
!repeek etag ,niaga tem lleW"
.t'ndid tsom yaw a ni boj sih evol ot demees eh rof
".sretsis yenaleD fo lluf tenalp a rof meht edart t'ndluow I
".sutats ydaer eralceD  .degrahc
,tenraG eht dnuora deppils seigrene etag eht ,eno
.kcehc-elbuod ot srats eht tohs ekeZ tub
.redloc yad rehtona s'doolb ruoy dna
.yllacimoc delbbow srae gib sih dna
,drawrof hcrul neddus a neht
,lortnoC namnnaT"  .derewsna neht
.lufituaeb si pup ym ,lufituaeb s'ehS  .neR ,efiw ym htiw yppah m'I tuB
.stnirp fo elpuoc a pu dleh dna
".hserf dna mraw enoemos htiw
!pup a em nevig tsuj sah efiw yM  !retteB"
.won gnicnyS  .24-HC ,taht ypoC"
,krow eht lla did sretupmoc ehT
.sevird eht pu mraw ot sehctiws eht deppilf neht
!taht elbuod lliw nheS erus m'I dna ,seot ym no em speek htaK  !on lleH"
.evird LTF s'tenraG eht no seitefas eht no gnippilf
,dekrep erew srae siH
,stegdag dna saet dna slio fo ograc lluf A
,noitseuq dnoces ruoy ot sa dnA
,ssorca nur reve dah neR repeeketag detamina tsom eht eb ot dah xirB
,daeh sih ekahs ot nrut s'neR saw tI
,dehsinav tenraG nahtaN eht dna despalloc etag eht yas dluow revresbo na ,orez tA
.retal tnemom a yawa llef ytivarg eht dna
,staes rieht otni evohs neddus a tlef
esrohetihW neewteb tniop 4L eht ta delttes ylbatrofmoc ,etaG lonaC
"!ti tuoba dab gnileef htiw gnitrilf er'uoy regaw d'I tub ,sey a s'tahT
,irauR nosmirC yb
.ni flesmih delkcub eh sa
".llew oot em wonk uoY"
.taes eht depmuht liat sih dna
".namnnaT ,won noitisop pmuj daer I
!uoy ot gnikaeps llits er'yeht tsael tA"
.namaremac eht ta gnilims saw ehs rehto eht ni elihw
,nwod tuhs evird LTF eht sa
nwonknu eht fo tahw swonk ohw dna
".tuo lortnoC namnnaT
.nirg eht denruter flow der ehT
,nokuY ,yramirp sti dna
,efil otni deremmihs etag eht ,tenraG nahtaN
./moc.yrrufos.iraurnosmirc no
ereht pu sehctiws eht gnikcehc ylbisnetso
.yltnesba stnirp eht ta gnikool
".ssam ruoy etats dna noitisop tropsnart ot ecnavda esaelP
".namnnaT ,efaS-etaG si 24-HC"   .EFAS PMUJ ETAG
".xirB s'tI  ?neR ,uoy tahT"
,hctiws a deppilf eH   .rae sih ni eciov rehtona tsuJ  .taht rof div deen t'ndid eh dna ,yawyna ,ssenisub nialp eb dluow ereht morf gnihtyrevE  .yalpsid eht tuc eH  ".pup ruoy dna htaK ot sdrager ym dneS  .lliw I wonk uoY"
.nirg dehtuom-nepo ,ediw a aremac eht evag eH
".ttum ygnar uoy ,ssorC nrehtuoS eht yojnE
,srettel neerg ni deralced yalpsid ehT
".rewsna ot senilced nameltneg a
.ygrene hcum oot dah syawla dah eH
,24-HC suoicerp sih morf sretem derdnuh a neve ton
.serutcip yppup eb dluow ti enigami ylno dluoc neR
".efil elohw ruoy rof meht htiw ruoh na edart t'ndluow I"
"!?tuoba gninnur htaK-dna-xirB elttil A  !?enigami uoy naC  !nos A
,denepo mih dniheb hctah ehT
.daeh sih koohs dna delkcuhc xirB
.nwod nips evird eht dehctaw eh sa dednopser eH
,gniliec eht ta decnalg neR
.oediv rof nottub eht tih eH
".ekeZ ,syawla sa ,gnimit taerG"
si
!rab trop eht ni tem eb ot gnitiaw tsuj hctib etuc emos dna
.elkcuhc ylno dluoc neR
!yawyna ,nwod gnilttes enigami t'nac I
irauR nosmirC yb
"!ttum uoy ,od nac nam a gniht tseb eht ylno s'tI
"?emit eht lla namow emas eht htiw derob teg t'nod uoY  ?tib a ton ,eixirB ,llitS  .ebyaM
esrevinu nwonk eht fo tsom ssorca werc sih dna flesmih gnirettacs ycnaf t'ndid eh tub
.flesmih ot mih deyarteb taes eht no liat sih fo pmuht eht dna
,timda ot dah neR
.pmuj ot setunim ytrihT"
,etag namnnaT ot mrah hcum od t'ndluoW
,yaled trohs a saw erehT
,riap suoegrog a erew yeht
,weiv eht dezingocer htob yehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.dneirf dlo na ees ro
daeh sih koohs flow der ehT
.setsat sih rof llams elttil a erew srae rieht fi neve
.won ecneuqes pmuj gnicnemmoC
.hgual tub pleh t'ndluoc neR
.emas eht ees I  .24-HC ,ypoc I"  .tnatsni na ni ssenisub ot kcab deppilf enot s'xirB
etag ehT  .lortnoC namnnaT si siht ,24-HC"  .ylper a htiw pu emoc ot gnivah morf mih devas xirB
.neR ,yaw ruoy ti evaH"
".niatpaC ,doog skooL"
dehgual ylpmis xirB
,etar ynA  .esruoc fO"
"!srats eht ot derehtet era uoy ti ni dna
,nirg a ni htuom sih fo tuo dellol eugnot s'flow der ehT
".syob ,ni depparts er'uoy epoH
"!lluf tenalp a htiw od dluow I tahw ,nam hO"  .kcab dekcik neR
".eno taerg a ti llac d'I sa wonk t'nod I tub
,neR ,efil a s'tI"   "!efil taerg a s'tI
,irauR nosmirC yb ”repeeK-etaG“
,ssalg tipkcoc eht edistuo ,sa dehctaw neR
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.abotinaM ni uoy tuoba erac yllaer t'nod ohw sretsis elpuoc a ,trop yreve ta lrig wen A
elzzum worran sih revo worbeye na desiar ekeZ
.ffo mih tuc flow kcalb ehT   " -- yeht erehw ,nam ,seugnot rieht htiw kcirt elttil siht evah yehT
.gnihtemos rof tekcop sih ni gniggid saw eh nehT
,niaga cim sih pu deyek
.neR ,namnnaT hguorht ssap ew emit yrevE"
"?swen eht draeh uoy evaH  !oS
”repeeK-etaG“:yojne esaelP
"?shtnom thgie ,neeb ti s'tahW
.dnim t'ndid eh tuB
neht
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy
,redlo yad rehtona er'uoy ,xirB ,etag siht dnet uoy yad hcaE"
,pup eht no desucof saw ehs ,eno nI
.rab wen a ssorca em ta gnikniw ecaf hserf A
,etam dnoces sih saw ti tiag eht morf llet dluoc eh dna
”repeeK-etaG“ saw sihT
.taeb ot hguot s'taht woN  !sruoh retfa od yeht sgniht eht ,naM  ?wonk uoy ,stsanmyg eeg-flah er'yehT  .abotinaM weN hguorht saw I emit tsal eht sretsis yenaleD eht was I
,gnihgual eb ot demees ohw
!ttum dlo yggahs uoy ,sah ti kniht I"
"?noitomorp a teg uoy ,tahW  .epoN"
.deggurhs flow der ehT
.tuo 24-HC  .namnnaT ,niaga sknaht ruO"
.kool detarepsaxe
.tsilkcehc pmuj-erp eht fo trap nwo sih no desucof saw lakcaj ehT
.pup yerg a gnildarc saw hctib flow yerg a ,meht nO
,werc eht htiw lausac oot saw neR taht deniatniam ekeZ
.ees ot snoitalletsnoc dna srats wen emos ,og ot esle erehwemos syawlA
,yalpsid eht fo dne rehto eht ta flow eht ot mih deyarteb elzzum sih no nirg eht dna srae sih fo kcirp ehT
.ruf sih fo kcalb eht dna mrofinu sih fo yerg eht tsniaga tuo gnidnats eugnot knip sih ,dennirg xirB
.lortnoC namnnaT si siht ,24-HC tropsnarT"
,noitisop pmuj ot esruoc a ni deyek dna
.nuf t'nsi ti naem t'nseoD  .ebyam ,eruS"
.taht tuoba wonk t'nod I"
,yreviled tpmorp no sunob taf a
,hserf dna mraw ti gnipeek eb ll'I ,eM
,hA"  .rewsna ot ton esucxe na mih evag ti tub ,s'etag eht dna pihs sih neewteb
redduhs tfos a evag pihs ehT
.esuap a saw erehT  ".won
.noitapicitna ni yalpsid eht sdrawot ni denael dna
.seye sih ni elkraps yldneirf a fo tnih a saw ereht dna
".pmuj rof eraperp dna sehctah eht nwod nettaB
.ti rof elbuort hcum oot evah t'ndid eh dna
!ti wonk uoy dna ,era uoy sa derb-erup sa m'I"
dna 1 WALC dna 41 taeH ni seirots trohs sah ohw
,yalpsid eht nO  ".detaitinI"
,ni flesmih delkcub neR
.pmuj erofeb od ot sgniht wef a evah I dna ,pu tsomla s'emit ruo ekil skool ,lleW"  .pu tas eH  ".neR
?wonk eh did tahw os ,yvaN eht ni neeb dah ekeZ tub
,ot gniklat erew uoy ohw daer ot detnaw uoy fi erutaef ydnah a saw ti tub
.lluh eht fo strap elbatibah eht hguorht ohce dluow eciov sih gniwonk
daer yalpsid eht nehW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sdnoces neetfif ni pmuJ
".sennot eerht-neves tniop xis-thgie-owt-evif-eerht gninnur era eW
.thgil htiw tipkcoc eht gnidoolf dna yleritne ti gnipolevne
.24-HC ,deespdoG
,mih fo tnorf ni lenap eht ot noitnetta sih denrut dna
.pmuj sdrawot nwod gnitnuoc detrats deedni dah yalpsid s'neR
?ereht ylenol leef reve uoy t'nod ,sediseB
.gnikaeps niatpac ruoy si siht ,tenraG nahtaN eht fo srerafecaps wolleF"
.ssorC nrehtuoS eht ot ffo m'I
.lakcaj eht ta revo dekool neR  .tollaM ekeZ
.daeh sih koohs eH
,etaG lonaC ot knil sti degnahc dah yalpsid s'retupmoc eht dna
!?lla taht sI  ?lla taht sI"
.taes sih fo tuo etarbiv ot tif demees eh dna ,daeh sih koohs xirB
,gnilriws eht dna
.etag eht ta noitisop pmuj ot ni detfird pihs sih sa
werc sih dna neR elihw
,dehgis dna kcab tas eH
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
,tif was eh sa pihs sih nar neR
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
.riahc sih ni kcab denael xirB
,regoR  .24-HC
.daeh sih koohs neR ,taes nwo sih otni gniltteS
.noitisop otni gnivom
si yrots s’yadot dna
".yenom emos ekam og s'teL  .tnellecxE"
"?wollahs ytterp lla ti t'nsI
"?enod ev'uoy taht lla taht si ,nos A"
.hcum oot eb thgim taht ,oN"
.tniop a dah xirB
.yalpsid llams eht morf mih ta dekool flow kcalb a neht dna
".xirB htiw pu hctac uoy tel d'I derugif ,gnippay uoy draeh
srae ralugnairt ,egral sih fo eno dniheb dehctarcs neR
.cim lanretni eht deyek eH  ".tuo
,pmalc gnikcod yna sa erus ,rettef a s'riahc s'niatpac tahT  .neR ,neR ,neR ,hO"
.niaga pu deyek mmoc ehT
.ti rof dnim a dah eh nehw romuh fo esnes dekciw a dna ,niagrab a rof srae doog dah yllareneg lakcaj ehT
.pihs sih sdrawot tuo dehcaer ygrene etihw-eulb tnaillirb
,railimaf a mih evag ekeZ
?ot pu neeb uoy evah tahW
".hsurc a tog ev'uoy kniht I
eht ta sevlesmeht dnuof neht dna
"?yletal ,straeh wen yna nekorB