.meht esirprus t’ndid hcihw ,daeh ym koohs I
.edalc gniworg ym ni ’erneG‘
ydobyreve ,hcrairtap s’ylimaf-isauq ruo dna ecnatsni toor eht sA
,suolaej werg eh sseug I…tub
lliW“	         ”.nuh ,daerb nikpmup emos htiw ti yrt tsum uoY“ ,delkcuhc
cisum evawropav ot gninetsil emit eerf sih sdneps sumoD
.yhpargoibotua eht rof detcelloc d’I seton evisneherpmoc eht ta gnirats flesym dnuof I
.ettal ecips nikpmup fo puc rehtona no deppis neht ,dias I
,tcetihcra na sa spetstoof sih ni gniwollof em detroppus eH
.yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
skrof ot deilppa sihT .eromyna rettam t’ndid emitefil rieht fo driht a hguorht tpels snamuh efil-laer tsom tcaf ehT
nemow dna nem gnivlovni ’secnamor dirul‘
.leef ot em detnaw yeht woh tlef ,yas ot em detnaw yeht tahw dias
.rekcins ot nageb krof yM
.nemow ot ton ,yllacificeps-deirram gnitteg ni
,hcteks ro ,eton ,repap yreve detcelloc I ,rettam eht no rehtruf gnikniht
.esoohc ot erom hcum os dna
t’ndid I .noisulcnoc neddus a dehcaer I ,allevon ecnamor yplup cireneg rehtona tey gnidaer hguorht yaw-flah ,lleW .od
retfA	         .smaerd neve rO .noitanigami eht ni detsixe ylno taht sdlrow lautriv neewteb gnicnuob flesym dnuof I sa
.rehto hcae ot yrarbil gnidnats yreve gnitcennoc snedrag larolf fo aes
.pihsnoitaler rieht fo devorppa I tub ,em morf ti dedeen meht fo rehtie taht ton ,lleW
,kni fo ylppus sseldne na htiw emac
.erneG knupmaetS htiw pihsnoitaler a gnimrof
ro evitarran ralimis a dewollof ytnelP
.wodniw lufituaeb eht tuo derats yllaer ylno I ,sgnirettum detatiga dna sesion gnipyt wef a morf edisA .stluser orez
,ee49b93e#alaG dnarG
!serneg retfa meht eman
,sruoh krow erom oN
reisae tlef dah gnihton ,revewoH
”!taht ot knird ll’I
em htiw kcuts sdrow
rood tnorf dekcolnu ehT .nibac gol citsur dezis-muidem a delbmeser erutcurts edam-nam
2e4d5f9a#taerteR s’retirW ,sraey eht revO
repap hcae litnu ,sllaw eht dna ,draobklahc eht
,a73e4f60#éfaC etinifnI dellac saw ot tnew d’I mis tsrif ehT
.flehs eht ffo ekat ot hcihw wonk t’ndid rednow ekildlihc yM
.éfaC etinifnI eht ta sesuovzedner ruo fo eno gnirud em ot kcab tnemetats ym detaeper noiZ
”.’erneG ecnamoR‘ em llac nac uoy“ ,denialpxe eh
,’eyR eht ni rehctaC‘ reh gnillac dekil I ,’eyR‘ dellac eb ot derreferp ehs hguohT
dna sdoirep emit suoirav ni deppart
.ecneirepxe wen a ekil ti dehcaorppa tub
,doof knuj fo yleritne desopmoc smis erew erehT
syad ekil demees tahw rof sdoog dekab dna seirtsap tnereffid ynam
.snrut koot ew ,syad lareves fo esruoc eht revo ,oS
:ksa ot suoiruc llits m’I tub
erew rehtie gnizama eb dluow thguoht I slevoN .eromyna
,noitciF cihpromoporhtnA saw noitidda tnecer tsom ruO
.seye ym fo eno ni dellew raet a sa
,levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
nihtiW .mis eht erolpxe dna edistuo erutnev ot dediced I
”,em no sesiarp paeh ot deen oN“
.reh wonk ot gnitteg ni tseretni erom elttil a dah tseretni evol s’retcarahc niam eht
.ytic a fo ezis eht noisnam dnaldoow evissam
”?etirw ot nalp uoy od tahW !etnaD ,taerg s’tahT“
ettal nikpmup rehtona no spis detcartsid neewteb deggurhs I ”.raf os
,meht ot
.8102 ni ”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“
,efaC etinifnI eht ot noiZ htiw sgnituo ym fo eno gnirud yllaicepse dnim ym fo kcab eht ta deniamer yehT .emit emos rof
,oga sraey em dellik noigiler s’daD dna moM
,em ot laer leef noitalumis eht ekam ot woh no ecivda lufesu yrev evag yehT
.metsyS eht fo tser eht erolpxe ot tuo tes I ,noiZ morf snoitcerid lufthgisni htiW
.enoemos htiw ecnamor a mrof ot ton nosaer a sa )foereht kcal ro( redneg s’enoemos weiv t’ndid eh woh em ot debircsed knupmaetS
”.muminim a ot stcilfnoc peek ot ekil dluow dna setunim wef a ni puteem rehtona evah I
,sdneirf htiw dekoj I .ylluf erom flesym desserpxe I .metsyS eht edistuo dah d’I efil suoiverp eht
.dettimda ehs ”,tniop riaF“
tuohtiW	         .em llet ot gniyrt neeb dah eyR
oD“	         ”.meht ot daed em redisnoc d’yeht…did yeht
.seitiralimis esolc dna secnereffid lacitehtitna rieht etipsed noitciF lacirotsiH sdrawot tcepser gnigdurgeb a dah ohw
,yrotsiH etanretlA htiw etaroballoc ot dekil osla mohw fo rettal eht ,noitciF lacirotsiH rehtorb evitaroballoc esolc s’erneG ecnamoR
,erutnevdA ,ysatnaF
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
negnilbiW eht edisni
,ylsuorogiv deddon eH ”!seY“ ”?yllaeR“
.sratS ehT rednU eyR dnA taehW ehT raeD deman
od saw oga sedaced elpuoc a gnidaolpu retfa did I gniht tsrif ehT
,derednop noiZ ”?yawa
taht sehcilc desurevo dna seport derit no deiler tsoM
.dne eht ot ylkciuq gnimmiks ro ,peelsa eb ot gnidneterp
.’riomeM‘ ,suoromuh elttil a eb ot detnaw yeht fi ro
ylimaf…htiw eno ylno eht ton m’I wonk ot dalG“	         ”ten' eht no kcab nwohs erew taht smis cilbup ym kciptin ot dekil daD ,em htiw hcuot ni peek ot rehtob did eh nehw dna
”.rellirhT lacitiloP tuo krof ll’uoy ,ni er’uoy pmuls siht morf yawa teg t’now tub
”.daeh ym otni spop taht gniht tsrif eht etirw tsuj ll’I ,ton fI
.detnaw I sa gnol sa rof egap hcae
.trohs siht tuc tsum I tub ,seigolopa ym ,yawynA“
.etirw dna nwod tis ot flesym rof ecalp a ekam ot dewolla eb yllaer t’ndluow I ,noitatuper tuohtiW
”,tcejorp siht htiw enod m’I retfa ti no krow ll’I“
erew ylimaf-isauq ruo nioj ot serneG gniwollof ehT
”ygolohtnA fleS-tsoP A :edalC“ ni yrots eno
.detelpmoc %99 ti gnivah retfa delecnac eb ot gnideen tcejorp gniogno na debircsed yeht sa spis evitalpmetnoc ,wols ym eciton ylluf t’ndid ohw
.em no desucof
.ti ekil tlef I revenehw peels dna tae dluoc I
,dias eyR ,rewsna t’ndid I nehW
”,no won morF“ .deksa I ”?tahW“
,stluc ekil erom leef dna ffo desolc ylivaeh
”!riomeM ,retal uoy eeS“
.yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb detide
yehT	         ”.ytsat s’ti ,si ’nikpmup‘ siht revetahw ,yaw eht yB“
,erneg-atem a ot nika erom si tI“
,rellirht lacitilop a no gnikrow trats ot tnaw reve uoy fi dna ,erneG ecnamoR eb ll’I
,mueanehtA notsoB eht neewteb delevart I ,gniw nairdnaxelA eht ta gnilevram sruoh gnidneps retfA
.10ff6f6f#mueanehtA nihtiw
ksed gnitirw ralucric
,retal skoob noillim A
.elpoep rehto htiw tcaretni ot em deriuqer
,daeh ym otni slevon erom detalumucca skrof ym fo yromem hcae sA .derob tog I
.flesym desimorp I
.flehs yreve no skoob eht yojne yllautca
.eugolaid ralimis dleh
.dlot eb tsum seirots lla toN
”?niaga em tuoba deirrow orhtnA sI“
tekram noitatuper ehT
,epacsdnal a ta tpmetta tsrif s’dlihc a ekil
.ekil dekool nibac gol a thguoht ecnegilletni laicifitra na tahw fo noitatimi deredner yllufniap
.dlrow eht fo edis rehto eht ot yawa nar tsuj I kniht ylimaf ym ,wonk I sa raf sA“
.niaga revo dna revo dna revo tuo yalp meht gniees retfa em ezama t’ndid
ylkeem deddon daetsni tub
.demrof pihsdneirf ruo retfa sedaced neve
.guh a evig ot revo denael ehs sa
.seye ybur htiw nosrep ylevil tub elap-ylhtaed a sa deraeppa ohw ,noiZ
.erom dna ,serusaert nwonknu ,sterces ,srebmahc neddih
,yticapac laud rof nibac moor-eno ym gnitavoner retfA
?daer ot emit eht ekat t’ndid eno fi hguoht seirarbil ot gniog saw doog tahW .dekool tsap eht
elgnuj eht ni erusaert tsol a retfa gniog stsigoloeahcra tuoba koob A .etnaD
dna yranib-non sa gniyfitnedI
,yldneirf htiw detcaretni I ,erehT
.rehtegot deppis ew dna
etirw ot skrof yna gnikam ekil leef reve I fI“
”?yako ,flesruoy fo erac ekat uoY“
.retpahc tsrif eht hguorht gnimmiks retfa dias I
eutats elbram a htaeneb
t’ndid I ,emit siht ylnO .hctarcs morf niaga detrats I ,ti gnipparcs retfA
hcneb a no nwod tas I
;noitidner lanif eht htiw tnetnoc tlef I ,dne eht
.detsixe regnol on stimil namuh taht saw dedaolpu gnieb retfa derevocsid I segatnavda tsrif eht fo enO
a otni nibac gnitirw llams a morf dednapxe
.em revo emac tahw wonk t’nod I ,yad siht oT
hcihw ,eramthgin diviv ylralucitrap a retfa
.sseldrager ,meht devol ylerecnis eH
.liat gnihsiws reh yb detcartsid yliraropmet neeb d’I sa srae dekrep htiw dennirg ehS
.emoh wen ym otni demrofsnart ti ,dessessop won I emit detoved dna gnikatsniap revo tub
,heH“	         .deggurhs I ”.snoitacilpmoc
,skoobtxet ,senizagam ,sllorcs
.ecalp rieht ni krof a tnes dah
,knupmaetS tuo dekrof nrut ni ohw dna
.reveileb tcefrep a sa em dlom ot gnihtyreve did yeht
na ni em tpek yllufsseccus noiZ ,roiretni dedworc eht ni taes a em dereffo yeht tnemom ehT
ekil derolpxe I smis cilbup rehto emac éfaC etinifnI eht
.seye latnemgduj ’stnerap ym fo setihw eht dekcimim ylhsrah
.lanummoc won ,moor gnivil eht ni em morf ssorca tas eH
.su dnuora deklat ro deklaw sresu detcartsid sa mlac gniniamer noisserpxe
.yaW ykliM eht tuohguorht sdlrow neila lacitehtopyh gnitaercer smis
,noitalumis knalb a ni pu ekow I retfa litnu detrats yllaer reven
.tsil tekcub ym no od ot detnaw reve ev’I taht gnihtyreve
.eugirtni ym gnissimsid
yM	         *** .ti htrow saw krow eht ,os nevE .tsrif ta ,enod naht dias reisae saw mis etavirp a droffa ot noitatuper erom gniniag tub ,smis rehto ot gnilevart dna noiZ htiw gnikaeps morf emos detalumucca ydaerla d’I
”?thgir ,dlrow eht ni emit eht lla tog ev’eW“
,emitdeb ym tsap yaw
ot em dedeen yeht yaw eht kniht ot em ecrof t’ndluoc sevitaler ym
.dehgual dna daeh ym koohs I
gnidroccA	         .ti fo hguone dah noiZ litnu sgniht elbaxifnu ylgnimees otni eno hcae denoollab dna sgniht laivirt detic tneilc ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
fo sacilper etarucca detneserp hcihw mis a ,10ff6f6f#mueanehtA dellac saw tisiv
.taerteR s’retirW eht ot denruter yltpmorp ohw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitatuper fo mrof eht ni ycnerruc nrae
,edurc ffo detrats mis tsrif yrev
tahw detanod d'yeht ,tnemhsinup sA
.em morf nosrep tnereffid a emoceb d’eh hcum woh
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,og ot em detnaw yeht erehw tnew ,hctaw ot em detnaw yeht tahw dehctaw ,sserd ot em detnaw yeht woh desserd I
”?suineg a I ma yhw ,yaw eht yB“
m’I…I“	         ”?ytilatrommi ruoy htiw od ot tnaw uoy od tahw
.did I tahT	         *** ”.oot dluohs uoY
efil ym ni stnemhsilpmocca tseggib eht nwod gnittoj
.hguone dah I yad eht litnu emulov derewol a ta ti tpek I ,eciov peed a gnivah etipsed dna ,elbisivni gnieb morf em detneverp emarf yknal ,llat yM .deriuqer sselnu
.skoob rehto htiw seitiralimis fo yvaeh oot derahs ro ercoidem
,gnidaolpu erofeB
lufituaeb woh ezilaer I did erofeb reveN
.tsap eht htiw dessesbo era
,em erofeb gnittis dneirf ym fo
,metsyS eht ot em democlew ohw sresu dnik dna ,nekopstuo
”,ernegbus a tsuj naht erom si msihpromoporhtnA“
.selims fo tsediw eht htiw elbat ruo morf pu tohs ylneddus I ”!ti s’tahT“
,krof ot woh ,sehtolc flesym evig ot woh no detcurtsni saw
ylno s’mis etavirp eht
yhpargoibotua na fo gnikniht…m’I“
,anihC fo yrarbiL lanoitaN
noissucsid gnol-sruoh
.gninruter krans reilrae ym
”,erus ton
,yrots ym revo yllufesromer dellum noiZ ”.metsyS eht edistuo tcnitxe erew sepyt suoigiler eht taht thguoht syawla I“
,mlaer latigid retfa mlaer latigid hguorht delbmuts I litnu gnivil nigeb yllaer t’ndid I
”?mis nwo yM“ .dias noiZ
dna metsyS eht hguorht yaw ym etagivan ot woh sa llew sa
,flah a dna yrutnec ym ni denrael evah I taht gniht eno si ereht fI“
era hcihw smis wef a wonk I“
”?sey ,snamuh htiw enod eb tonnac taht seitilanosrep gniyalpsid nuf erom evah nac uoy
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,semithcnul gnirud yrarbil loohcs eht ni daer ylikaens ot deganam I skoob dedaolnwod eht sulp
,emitgnirps ni tserof rebmit naciremA htroN tsav a naht erom gnihton ylgnimees
smis dnuof I ,erutcetihcra elbissopmi dna erutan tsol desacwohs taht secalp sediseB
yrt ot ytinutroppo eht em evag ,nrut ni ohw dna
.rojam oot gnihtoN“
,flesym fo noisrev dekrof a gnitaerc ylneddus yb ti detartsnomed I
.mis alaG eht ot yawa deknilb I emit emas eht ta em ot emac thguoht gnisuma na ,ylimaf wen ym tuoba gniknihT
.tsilanoitasrevnoc tnellecxe na osla erew yehT
uoy taht skniht eH“ .denaorg I
yojne ot dewolla saw I
,retirwepyt nwo sih no yawa depyt ylregae ecnatsni dekrof ym sa nibac eht ni gniyats tsuj raeb t’ndluoc I nehW
.nib hsart eht otni meht tnes neht
gnidaer tlef yeht sa yllaicepse ,rehtie egrup eht evivrus t’ndid telbat lanosrep nwo yM
.ettal iahc rieht fo tser eht gnihsinif retfa delkcuhc yehT
.stnerapdnarg dna stnerap ym
,laudarg ffo detrats yehT
I	         ”.em detcerruser metsyS eht ,yad taht retfa tub
,gnihtyna yas t’ndid llits I
.oot tekram noitatuper eht gnisu deriuqer mis a gningised dna gnisahcruP
s’eyR	          .sniats gnivael ,hguoht sehctolb kni ekil deregnil sracs ehT
.)tnemesuma gnilggig s’noiZ ot hcum ,ti deruoved ylrettu dna ni daerb nikpmup ym deknud gnivah retfa(
si yrots s’yadoT dna
fo snaf drah-eid eseht rof mis a etaerc depleh I ,yadretsey tsuJ“
,tnemesuma rettu ym dna nirgahc reh ot hcum
,meht gnihsilbup erofeb stpircsunam dna ,stfard ,saedi ,seirots degnahcxe ,deklat eW
,daer draobklahc eht no eton
”?sey ,erutuf retteb a rof ereh emac uoY
nI	         .nuS eht fo swodahs gnitsac
.ekal a gnikoolrevo
ylkciuq yrev denrael I dna snoisrev dekrof yM .oot
a dliub ot em detnaw ohw ,semag gniyalp-elor noitca-evil
)tnemeveihca etamitlu eht gnieb gnidaolpu(
éfaC etinifnI eht ta srehtegot-teg ylkeew deludehcs-won ruo gnirud noiZ morf ecnatsissA
.thgin taht retfa esol ot tfel gnihton dah I“
.daer neeb tsuj dah tahw fo noitcellocer yrrulb a ylno
.enim dna ,thgiled sih ot hcum
.esare ot gniyrt neeb d’I seiromem desserper ot kcab gnikniht ro seton eugav nwod gnittoj rehtie ,ksed taht ta tneps erew syad ym
,sicoV sumoD yb ”edalC erneG“
ot detnaw I tahw em deksa noiZ nehw ot kcab thguoht I erom eht
tahw won dootsrednu
.t’ndid ew ,tsrif ta toN
fi tub ,flesym dedaolpu I wonk t’nod yehT
.ytirahc hcruhc eht ot denwo I snoissessop elttil
gniticxe sa meht dnif t’ndid I
,yrotsih tuohguorht seirarbil suomaf
”edalC erneG“   yojne esaelP
niamer t’ndid tub denrut sdaeh wef A
htiw detapissid fles dlo ym
.nwod gnitirw derehtob I hcihw fo enon
,kcab em dloh ot enoyna tuohtiW
.erots yot tsrif sti gnitisiv dlihc yppah a
retfa edalc eht fo rebmem dednetxe na emaceb noiZ nevE
.efil ruoy ni retpahc wen a siht redisnoc dluohs uoy ,won roF .dnatsrednu I“
yltneuqerf ot etirovaf ym meht gnoma
edalc edO eht morf rohtua knuks gnimrahc yldrawkwa
mis dehsinif ym dellac I
”,neht mis nwo ruoy deen ll’uoY“
kaerb yraropmet a gnikat erofeb ssergnoC fo yrarbiL naciremA dlO eht dna
dna noissimmoc mis a htiw erew yeht ysub woh denoitnem yeht nehw raeppasid ot ylohcnalem ym rof ylno ,éfaC etinifnI eht ta niaga noiZ nioj ot redro ni noitalosi ym morf yawa ekorb I .dessap syad wef rehtonA
,tludA gnuoY ,noitciF ecneicS
.regnol rof yats ot tnaw ll’I ,dekrower dna detide eb ot deen ll’siht fI“
hcihw retirwepyt elyts-dlo na dedulcni serutaef etirovaf ym fo enO
.daeh ym otni pop ot aedi taerg a desuac
,kcab tohs I ”,sesimorp oN“
,nexiv yrtlus a liof sih dna noil emosdnah a ,yas ,si tsinogatorp ruoy fi tub
,sterger dna seruliaf tsap rof flesym desitsahc I erom eht ,hguoht efil ym no detcelfer I erom ehT
enO	         .srehto ot pu flesym denepo ylwols I sa
si dlrow eht taht deveileb ylimaf yM“	         ”.ti s’taht tub
.deggurhs I hcihw ot ,deksa noiZ
fo desopmoc epacsytic eritne na
.tfard hguor s’allevon eht gnidaer ni detseretni eb d’I fi deksa krof ym ,syad fo elpuoc a
”?yako ,drah oot sevlesruoy hsup t’nod tsuJ
.yrrac dluoc secnatsni dekrof lareves ym dna smra ym revetahw esoohc I ,oS
,negyxo ekil sgnul ym fo tuo yleerf delbbub rethguaL
.’ococoR‘ sa syawhcra dna ,sllaw ,sgniliec etanro yllacismihw eht dezingocer I ,erutcetihcra fo hcum wonk t’ndid I hguohtlA
,noisufnoc reehs ym gniciov derebmemer I
saw ereht emit ym gnirud edam I sdneirf lanrete eht fo
,enoyreve rof ton s’tI“
tseretnisid…ym derevocsid d'yeht nehw secaf s’rehtom dna rehtaf ym ni yruf eht nwod delbbircs yllanif d’I
”,ylimaf…yM“	         ”?etnaD ,mohw morF“
syawllah tnagavartxe sti fo eno gnikoolrevo
,renroc eno ni elbat pot-retnuoc etinarg dna nehctik a htiw roiretni nepo na ot del
,enim ot ettal rieht deppat yehT
”.oot no krow ot tnaw I saedi rehto emos tog ev’I
.tsixe dluoc wenk reven I setsat dna ,sthgis ,sdnuos ,sllems latigid decneirepxe sesnes evif yM
”?won skoob etirw annaw uoY“ …ot detnaw I
.rehtaf ym htiw gnilaed ot kcab em thguorb tI“
,etnaD eman laer ym yb em dellac rehtie esle
,noitcurtsnoc eht hsur
a ni nos tsegnuoy eht sA
”,snoitacol lacirotsih fo pu edam sepacsdnal etacirtni etareneg ot ekil I“	         .sevitaerc
yromem eht no kcab dekool I sa neve
,dias dna em ta devaw ehS
.elit yb elit dna kcirb yb kcirb ti tliub ylwols tub
.ecaf nwo ym no ees ot elbissop saw thguoht reven I seye sih ni tnilg a gniraew
”.yhpargoibotua taht revo gnillum nibac taht ni pu deloh syad ruoy dneps uoy ,daetsnI
.daer ot tnaw tsuj
,metsyS eht ot gnidaolpu naht
”.eerf t’nera smiS .noitatuper niag ot deen ot gniog er’uoy ,esruoc fO“
.denetfos nworf derruf-etihw-dna-kcalb s’eyR
ot del yrautcnas latigid eht nihtiw tneps syad wef tsrif yM
.nam reerf a nibac eht fo tuo deklaw I dna ,sredluohs ym morf deraeppasid sraey ytnewt fo thgiew eht ,sdnoces nihtiW
,stcejorp deggolkcab tuoba noitasrevnoc ruo ni detsevni yletelpmoc dna dexaler
revE	         .tnemom a retfa dias yllanif I
em fo ecnatsni dekrof a rehtar ro—em ot denialpxe ehs
ot flesym decap ylregae I ,syad roF
”,snis tsap s’ytinamuh
ciahcra erew seirarbil eht nihtiw lairetam gnidaer elgnis yreve tsomla ,hguoht stelbat eht ekilnU
;snossel yrotsih ni nees ylno sgnittes
.seno dna seorez eb ot laer oot tlef llits snoitasnes ehT
,skcabdrah ,skcabrepap
.seirots ym tuo nalp
.mih ta ylknalb derats I
.llew sa yaw gnol a depleh
”?PRAL ot ekil uoy oD
ot sleehw no draobklahc gnirobhgien a sulp
,levon a gnihsinif retfa yltcerid tiuq senolc latigid ym tel ot ton
efil ym ,tup ylpmiS	         .retal seirutnec
,detacilpmoc yrev si tsap eht taht si ti
”!suineg tnaillirb ,tnaillirb A
.yrarbiL yretsanoM
sa llew sa ,stneve cirotsih fo stnemtcaneer detsoh taht smis
.gnihgual retfa deilper krof s’noiZ
gnihtyreve tsomla nees d’ohw nezined metsyS a ekil ekops noiZ
saw no sucof ot detnaw yllaitini I gniht tsrif ehT
.ksat naelucreh a ekil tlef emoh remrof ym morf yawa gniklaW   sicoV sumoD yb
pu deyats I sa peels tsniaga gnithgif ,detpurretni gnieb ,srennid ylimaf drawkwa
s’tel ,saedi koob rehto
.yawa gninnur ym ot pu gnidliub syad eht gniliated yltnevref neeb d’I ,erofeb sruoH
”?yrruf a yllaer yeht era ,eciwt ro ecno noitpircsed eht ni pu thguorb ylno s’ti tub ,yrruf a s’retcarahc niam a fI ?tahW“ .denworf eyR .deugra I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,seires yrots naipotsyd yrruf gniogno sih sedulcni hcihw
fi neeb ev’dluow levon ecnamor dab eno taht retteb hcum woh tuoba gnikniht
ssergnoC fo yrarbiL naciremA dlO eht edisni erutaretil dessucsid ew sa—
,ereh er’uoy taht won
,erutnevda egareva na tsuj si
.puc ym nwod tes I sa deddon I ”.od
.sgnidnuorrus sseldnuob ym fo esnes a gniniag
”.krow emos deen ll’tI“
”,yllautca ,dab toN“
noitacilpud eht gnieeS
,ti detpecca ylregae I
.2e4d5f9a#taerteR s’retirW
.pu gniworg morf seiromem etirovaf ym dna
regnol on m’I taht won em llac ot gniog era sllabfoog esoht tahw rednow I“
,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb ”edalC erneG“ saw sihT                   ”?’riomeM‘
draeh ro nees reven eb ot neeb dah evitcejbo gnolefil ym
,dnim ym fo kcab eht ta gnileef gniggan siht saw ereht ,daetsnI
,noitciF naitfarcevoL dna lamronaraP deman ’sretsis‘ niwt s’erneG rorroH
wodniw ssalg a dna riahc cimonogre yzoc a neewteb
,sretsis regnuoy sih ot em decudortni erneG rorroH nehw ot ralimis
”?meht ot tuo hcaer ot nalp uoy
,ksed gnitirw ym fo yteritne eht gnimmirb emit revo
dellac mis rehtona ni laever revoc koob evitaroballoc s’yrotsiH etanretlA dna knupmaetS gnidnetta erofeb ,yad enO
,gnittiuq erofeb seye sih dellor ecnatsni dekrof yM
.tnedicca yb noitasrevnoc a otni deklaw I
a dna sremocwen rof tniop nwaps a sa gnivres esuohthgil cinoci sti dna airdnaxelA fo yrarbiL tneicna eht htiw
,amarD ,romuH ,efiL-fo-ecilS
.em htiw dekoj yeht dna ,edalc ym htiw
”.esrevinu eht fo dne eht litnu od ot gniog era uoy taht lla si taht ,esiwrehtO
.metsyS eht fo lla ni sretirw tseb eht eb ot srovaedne detcennoc tub etarapes ruo ni rehto hcae gnitroppus
,doohdlihc ecnis em ot gnignilc ssenevisicedni yhs fo tnanmer tsal eht levarnu dluow ti taht wonk I did elttiL
yb edam erew seciohc ym ,rebmemer dluoc I ecnis
”?éfac siht ,morf krow ot gniog uoy era esle erehW“
.nirg ym gnirahs ,dootsrednu yletaidemmi yehT
.em ot seiromem esoht gnidnes yltpmorp
erneG rorroH yb denioj noos
dezilaer em depleh rehtegot noiZ dna knupmaetS htiw noissucsid gnol a tub
.eiteews ,suineg a m’I ,thgir er’uoY“
elcyC fleS-tsoP eht daer ot erus eb dnA .”letoH kcirevaM“
,ylimaf suoigiler
”,nosaer on htiw slamina meht sekam tsuj dna yzal gnieb s’retirw eht sselnu toN“
,krof tsrif eht saw erneG ecnamoR ”.revetahW“
eht ot dniw fo stsug tselpmis eht morf
.spohs eeffoc dna ,srab eciuj ,seirekab ,sefac
,noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
teG“	         ”.yawa teg ot detnaw ylno…I“
!suineg a er’uoy ,noiZ“
,pu gniworg doohdlihc yhtlaehnu na sa ezingocer ot emoc dluow I tahw otni ecneulfni rieht lla roF .kniht ton tuB
htiw eltsac cihtoG deliated hgih
,ylevil a yb detsoh gnirehtag mis a ta noiZ denioj d’I retfa ecnetsixe otni emac ohw
,daer ot detnaw syawla d’I skoob sseldne eseht no pu thguac I regnol ehT
.tsrif ta ,em demlehwrevo sevlehs ynagoham eht gnola pu denil ynam os gniees tsuJ
fo esuaceb espylacopa na ni
a dna ,renroc etisoppo eht ni moor gnivil elbatrofmoc a
,hguoht emit revO
.loohcs hgih etal ni seitinutroppo eht dnif dluoc neve I fi
,noitcif yrruf gnidaer/gnitirw elihw
htiw ehcadaeh gnittilps yletulosba na depoleved I ,esiwrehtO .emit emas eht ta gnihtemos gnidaer saw I elihw ron
,’scitehtsea knuphtoG-oeN‘ llac ot dekil yeht taht sehtolc desserd
ot dereffo metsyS eht tahw no
revenehw decrof gnileef tuohtiw delims I dna
hcae fo serised citehtsea dna ,stnaw ,sdeen eht ot deretac noisnam eht nihtiw ’esuoh‘ yrevE
.daerd laitnetsixe fo lluf gnittes a rof aedi na em evag neht
ro em morf yawa gnikool tuohtiw detsaob yeht
.dnik emos fo erusolc emos em evig tsael yrev
a ekil deraeppa tluser dne eht ,tsrif tA
enO	         .dessefnoc d’I sfeileb eht detcidartnoc
?uoy era ,seitilibissop gnilletyrots eht tuoba gnikniht yllaer ton era uoy tuB“
.eb ton deen noitcif tub
.noissefnoc ym emac
.NGISLLAC htiw
,em evag doG segelivirp wef eht gnoma saw tahT .kniht
,ngised dnarg eht ni tcepsa hcae htiw etacirtni eb ot woh dna
eht ta ro ,sgniht emos kcapnu em pleh thgim ti ,gnihtyna fI