yhw gniksa er'uoy fi tuB .aretec te ,aretec te ,stifeneb htlaeh desoppus ,erutan htiw eno eb ot gnitnaW" dehsilbatse eh
.snoisacco elpitlum no yas taP draeh dah eh eno
,edirts sih ni pep
.dalcyks flesmih gniredner yllanif
.esnes ekam ot detrats yad eht fo seitirailucep eht lla dna ,nrut ot nageb daeh s'taog eht ni sraeg eht
?ti dluoc ,doog taht leef t'ndluoc tI
?eh t’ndid ,seye dah eh ,lla retfA
,yhw wonk t'nod I
".anavrin ekil sleef ti..."
"?esirprus eht htiw od ot gnihtyna evah ot neppah siht dluoW"
,taht ekil fo dnik s'ti ,lleW"  .deddon werdnA
.pu ti deppiz ylreporp dna
.siht ekil rehtaew toh ni yllaicepsE .tol a taews I tub ,gnitsugsid adnik si siht ,yako
.hsut reh gnibbur
,drawpu dna drawtuo sdnah nepo sih thguorb eh
dnats ylno dluoc werdnA
"?ton yhw ,naem I"
".gnihtoos fo dnik s'ti …gniht elohw eht
.kcolbnus fo elttob a pu gnidloh
,yleneres dna ylwolS
relooc eht morf koot eh hciwdnas tsrif eht dehsinif tsuj dah taP ,elihwnaeM
,ydob s’taP ta gnikool ,revewoH
seidob rieht gnisopxe
,no sdud fo tes a dah llits taht ereht nosrep ylno eht saw eh ,llet dluoc eh sa raf sa ,tcaf nI
.dekan erew meht fo lla
.sedaps ni ti gnileef saw taog eht ,saw esirprus fo etisoppo eht revetahW
.ylleb elbazis sih gnittap
,nwo sih naht taeh siht ni retteb hcum gniraf saw edarmoc sselgnihtolc sih fo ydob eht taht
?did eh sa hcum sa sehtolc sih gniddehs yojne eh did yltcaxe yhw ,oS
.gnimmiws og annog m'I"
".eugra ot toh oot s'tI
nekat dah yeht htap eht drawot kcab dekool dna °081 a did eanirpac gnituot-kcapkcab eht taht neht saw tI
,ecnardnih a eb ot gnivorp saw meht no nwod gniraeb nus ehT
.emit dnoces a rof daeherof sih morf noitaripsrep eht debbur eh sa niaga dehgis werdnA  ".peY"
cisab eht naht rehto
drawrof daeh sih denrut eH
,sediseB !yrgnuh m'I"
,revol lautum rieht naht rehto enon dnuof owt eht
.mlap sih ni eldnah relooc eht dna
.flesmih ot derednop erunoc noom-flah ehT
,tfos eht dehcaer yllanif riap eht
…ti od yllanosrep I
.gnitad nageb yeht ecno
,erohc eht htiw dehsiniF
,tsenoh yltcefrep eb ot tub"
?thgiR .ytinutroppo eht fo egatnavda ekat I riaf ylno s'tI
.nuf etavirp fo tib elttil yldneirf a htiw esiwrehto meht ecnivnoc ot elba saw eninac gnivinnoc eht
,teef owt reh no gnidnats dna pu flesreh gnikcip
.saw yllausu ehs tirips eerf eht gnieb
,decnelis gnitrilf rieht htiW
.sehtolc snas ylno
.tops teews a tih werdnA revenehw naom lanoisacco eht tuo gnittel neve
,esac eht morf sehciwdnas fo riap a tuo gnillup
doof htiw ecaf sih gniffuts naiva eht htiW
,hcaeb yrotadnam-gnihtolc
,tuo yad elbayojne na ot emac ti nehw thguoht tsrif s'eugirtaP ron s'werdnA rehtien saw ti elihW
…dlrow eht ni gniht tsrow eht eb t'ndluow ti sseug I
!yltcaxE"  "!wE"  "…gnol oot rof gnittis morf taes tew eht
,mih ot txen taog eht ot denrut taP
ylniam dnuof eb nac eH
,deppord dah eh gnihtyreve detcelloc eh sa dednopser taP
,hsinif ot ecnahc a dah neve taP erofeB  ”-uoy era
,sknurt sih fo tuo deppets eh sa delims werdnA
.syob eht morf yawa htap reh no deunitnoc eldoop ehT  "!em tpmet t'noD"
.gniht msinoitibihxe elohw eht teg I
".dekan yllauxes gnieb sa elbayojne sa tsuj si
".esle erehwyreve hcaer ot elba saw I"
.detcepxe naht redrah eb ot gnivorp saw dneirf elttil suoveihcsim rieht rof hcraes eht ,dessap emit sA
,sevil rieht gnivil dna ,nuf gnivah ,gnixaler
.tnednecsnart enilredrob saw
"?uoy lliw ,nwod gniht taht tuP"
,tius yadhtrib etihw-duolc sih ni denroda woN
teknalb hcaeb eht no nwod relooc eht deppolp taP
,relooc sih ot txen dehcrep llits
.msidun s'tI .enif ,thgir llA"
yrrebnikceH sucraM retirw wollef yb detide saw yrots sihT
".neercsnuS"  .deksa werdnA
,ria eht ni ttub reh gnikcits ,desaet icreP
",neve hcaeB senoJ ro ,hcaeB nothgirB ot enog ev'dluoc ew taht si gniyas m'I lla ,kooL"
...mih dlot eugirtaP tahw derebmemer eh ,nehT
nades depmarc s'drib eht ni etis eht ot looprac eht ,ecneH
,sdik egelloc eht
:ti etah yletulosba I dna od tsuj I tub
"?relooc eht morf gnihtyna tnaw uoY .werdnA ,oY"
redluohs sih morf lewot eht deppord dalcyks eht
".si esirprus reh tahw fo aedi na evah I kniht I"  "?tahW"
,dennapdaed eh ”,taerg ,hO"
.daeh sih fo pot eht gnola decnad
yranidroartxe erom hcum emoceb dah efil sih taht timda ot dah eh tub
.gnihctaw-elpoep emit sih dneps ot dediced werdnA
…anavrin ekil sleef tI
,retaw eht ni dnuora llab hcaeb a gniworht
,teknalb hcaeb reh no gnitser god desserdnu eht dnuof dah yeht ecnO
".em 'gnihton' t'noD .no emoC"  ".gnihtoN"
"..."  "..."  ".noitseggus a tsuj saw tI
,egassam utpmorpmi eht deyojne dna
.mih edisgnola dewollof werdnA ,gurhs a htiW
did I tahw od syawla dluoc uoy
.tsael eht yas ot ,sdoom fo tseb eht ni riap eht evael t'ndid
"?emoc annaw uoy ,taP
,hguoht ,reh rof yletanutrofnU
.draeh ylneddus oud eht "!HAEY !OOHOOW"
rettiwT no dnuof eb nac mohw fo htob
,nylkoorB ni emoh s'werdnA morf evird gnol-flah-a-dna-ruoh na eb ot deneppah hcihw
!msidun si siht tuB"  "?tib a ylnO"
".tius yadhtrib ym otni gnignahc ton m'I"
.rettiwT dna ytiniffAruF no
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dnoces sih gnieye won saw dna
.stius gnihtab rieht yb derevoc ydaerla erew teg t'ndid yeht secalp ylno ehT
,yrehcuabed ni serutnevda sih dniheb nosaer elos eht ylirassecen t’nsaw eninac ehT
,htiw revo trap ysae eht htiW
.eldoop nmad eht dnif dluoc nem owt eht ylno fi ,woN
.detibihorp-gnihtolc ton ,lanoitpo-gnihtolc saw hcaeb eht ,esruoc fO
.erofeb naht relooc seerged evif leef rehtaew eht edam
.evaw a htiw icreP ot kcab dellac taP
,mra sih htiw ffo meht gnipiW
.dnim s'taog niatnuom eht ni tuo dnats meht edam tsuj meht tuoba gnihtemoS
"?ngis eht ees ton …uoy did ,tiaW"
.ynapmoc doog ni eb dluow taog eht tsael ta
,elpuoc ognimalf ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,detsurt werdnA
",elihw a rof ereh neeb ev'I ?swonk ohw ,lleW"
.ecnelis evitaler ni pirt rieht deunitnoc owt eht ,setunim wef txen eht revO
saw sihT      ".thgir ,hO"
,daeherof sih no pu gnidaeb saw taews ,sselehtenoN
.reveostahw ssenisub ynnuf on ,gnihcuot lausnes on
,rewsna na rof tiaw ot gnirehtob neve toN
.naiva eht ot kcaspank eht detneserp dna mih ot kcab sih denrut werdnA
.ruomatem doog a edam eH
,kcab s'icreP ssorca kcolbnus gnidaerps nageb werdnA
"…hgU"  "!ti edih gnikcuf t'nod nehT"
osrot erab sih tsniaga ezeerb ytlas eht fo noitasnes eht
.ytirucesni eht rof dna taeh eht rof htob
,deksa eninac eht "?stnap tahW"
".dekrap ew retfa no ti tup ydaerla ew tuB ?neercsnuS"
"!ho …tuoba em ot gnihtyna yas t'ndid ehS ?esirpruS"
.thgit oot egdims a leef ot detrats sknurt sih fo dnabtsiaw eht dna
,detressa eh "'!esirprus a s'ti'
,naeco eht sdrawot gnillorts nageb dna denrut ehs sa dehgis ehs
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
!did I esruoc fO"  .kcab derif taP
.tsap semityalp morf xnijih yknik eht lla tuoba ecsinimer tub pleh t’ndluoc eh ,ti no gnirednoP
".yb deklaw tsuj ew eno ehT"  "?ngis tahW"
.dah ehs taht ngis yna wohs t'ndid ehs
.dnabtsiaw sih otni sbmuht sih gud eanirpac eht
.lla retfa stius gnihtab ogrof ot dediced ohw seno ylno eht t'nerew icreP dna taP tuo snrut tI
.draugefil retto eht pu gnittahc
,detcejbo taP ”!thguoht taht dloH"
DEWOLLA GNIHTABNUS EDUN :ECITON
.rac eht fo tuo deppets yeht ecno eot ot daeh pu derehtal meht fo htob ehT
,dednopser ehs ",revetahw
,dnah sih otni neercsnus eht fo pollod a dezeeuqs eh sa
egareva eht sa dedworc sa t'nsaw tI
nottoc ytaews fo gnir eht fo lavomer ehT
.ay ekam annog s'eno oN"
,yalpsid lluf no doohnam sih htiw ereht doots taP ,hguone eruS
.taeh eht tuoba gnorw t'nsaw taP
dna tsumifillew@ sa
".erom deen I won tub ,haeY"
.rehtie pleh t'ndid taeh remmus eht ni hcaeb eht ot rac eht morf seirteliot dna doof rieht gniluaH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sserdnu fo etats sih decarbme dna
.denihw taog niatnuom ehT
ezeerb remmus mraw a sa larutan sa gnihtemos morf tnemeticxe na hcus leef oT
dah ruomatem sih dna ,dneirflrig sih
".srobhgien ym fo yna gnihsalf ton dna edisni m'I ecno …od I"
.decaf yeht noitcerid eht morf ni dehsur dniw fo tsug neddus a ,euc no fi sA
ezilaer ot mih koot ti gnol ylinnacnu woh nialpxe t’ndid taht ,revewoH
.pu shgiht eht morf edun mih gnivael
".gniyrt rof sporp uoy evig attog"
".wonk ew ,haey haeY"
"!gniog teg s'tel ,thgir llA"
.daeha gniklaw ,dereehc eh
".won yb ssorg agem nettog ev'dluow ti ,taeh siht htiW
,derewsna drib eht ",mmhmM"  "?gnihtooS"
.ytidun lausac ot demotsucca yrev emoceb ydaerla dah werdnA
.daeh sih otni tperc thguoht ralugnis
.dne na ot emoc tsum sgniht doog lla
,gnillactac on ,secnalg driew oN
,ylleb reh no nwod flesreh dial ehs sa ,deifiralc icreP
:mih kcurts noitazilaer eht ,ylnedduS
.ees ot enoyreve rof tuo srekcep sih fo htob gnivah ot evah dluow naiva na noitcaer lamron eht t'nsaw ylniatrec ti tub
"?tsidun a uoy erew nehw ecniS"
",yllacinhcet ,lanoitpo-gnihtolC"  .decseiuqca eH
:yadot tuo sreoghcaeb fo tnuoma tneced a llits erew ereht tub
.mih deinapmocca taht riap eht ot kcab dekool eH
"...raews I ,tuo dekcik su teg annog s'ehS"
,ni evag naiva eht
,sgel ,ydob ,smra ,daeH
".erofeb edun eht ni uoy nees t'nevah I ekil toN ?tahW"
.flesmih ot thguoht werdnA ?eroM
,tuo detniop eh ",spih ruoy neercsnus ot deen uoy neht ,uort pord annog er'uoy fI"  "?yhW"  .mih retfa llac erunoc eht "!no dloH !tiaW"
,yltnatsni tsomlA
,tpek eh taht ynapmoc eht htiw tuo gnignaH
.delwocs taog eht "?yllaer …eduD"
.skcab evitcepser rieht no stops hcaer-ot-drah eht teg rehto hcae depleh neve yeht
llits deniamer icreP elihw
erom tib a htiw gniklaw eb ot deneppah drib eht woh eciton tub pleh t'ndluoc eH
"?kcapkcab eht morf gnihtemos no sdnah ym teg I fi dnim uoy oD“
"?hcaeb siht eb ot dah ti yhw reh ksa ot rehtob uoy diD"
,sevaw eht ni tuoba gnihsalps icreP dna
,sevaw wollahs eht ni tuoba gnihsalps llits saw icreP
"?dekan eb ot tsuj ffo sehtolc ruoy ekat ot tnaw uoy dluow yhw tuB
,ysaerg gnitteg riah eht ,sralloc trihs tew eht ,sessalg ym otno gnillaf daeherof ym no spord eht
"…ydob elohw ruoy s'ti nehw tub
,ecnetnes sih dehsinif eh erofeB
.worb s'werdnA no demrof taews fo spord tsrif eht sa
.dekan yllautca saw enoyreve
,msidun gnivlovni tra gninoissimmoc syojne taht retirw yrruf a si ohw ,eugirtaP yb ”nosinnuG ta dekaN gnitteG“
.noitamrofni detcepxenu ssecorp ot tnemom a gnideen yleniuneg
ecnatsid eht ni ffo elpuoc ognimalf redlo na
.stros fo elur a gnikaerb saw eh ekil
.seye sih desolc dna
,seltsacdnas ekam ot woh nos sih gnihcaet rehtaf okceg a
".taht tcepxe t'ndiD"
.segareveb dna doof eht otni gud dna
"-il sleef ti dias ohw eno eht er'uoy ,yeH"
"!ereht thgir eb ll'eW"
.dnuof eb ot erehwon tiusmiws sih dna
.yrotnevni rieht hguorht gud eugirtaP sa
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tuoba dna tuo tsuj saw ereh enoyrevE
.drawrof pets a koot eh emityreve liat sih gnihsiws dna flesmih ot gnimmuh
,lleW"  ".ereh tuo edun gnieb gnihserfer erom tol a s'ti kniht I
,dnuorg eht no relooc eht detser taP sA
.prah ssalg a ekil ydob sih deyalp icreP sa smoordeb etavirp fo srood dekcol eht dniheb ylevisulcxe tiebla
.ni delttes ylkciuq eanirpac dna erunoc eht
,tiaW“ ,dekramer torrap ehT
"-nk em gnittel dnim uoy oD“
".nwod looc ot detnaw uoy fi
,llew sa dewollof taog ehT
,tiucsib hserf nevo na no rettub saw ti ekil ereirred sih ssorca neercsnus gnidaerps dnah sih
"?ydaerla gnitae er'uoY"
,detcejretni eugirtaP "!sgodnroh ay ,ereht ysaE"
,setunim net tsap eht rof yawklaw nedoow ,gniretnilps eht dna
,pmad leef ot gninnigeb saw trihs sih fo gnir eht
reveirter nedlog gnihtemosytnewt a dna
.elanoitar reh gnitbuod nageb oud eht
"?naem ot desoppus taht s'tahW"
.srehtaef neerg sih gnola taews fo kcal tcnitsid eht fo eton gnikat
riah s'taP fo sdnarts ehT
"?gniht 'nees gnieb fo llirht' elohw ehT .wonk uoY"
,ti deyojne eh yhw otni hcum tup yllaer reven eH
:dias flesti ngis eht tahw ,rehtar tub ,esirprus a fo hcum saw taht flesti ngis eht t'nsaw ti ,revewoH
,noisulcnoc rehtona ot gnimoc erofeb neercsnus eht tuoba stnemetats suoiverp s'taP fo emos no tcelfer ot tnemom a koot werdnA
.evig ot kcuf yratilos ,elgnis a ron worb sih gnola taews fo pord a ton htiw
,detats gnieb tahT
.mih erofeb enecs eht ta erats dna
”,ereh taht tuoba yrrow ot evah t'nod I tub …riaF"
"…tsinoitibihxe na dna
nwod raewmiws sih deggut taog eht
,werdnA delcric torrap sselstnap won eht
"?uoy t'nera ,won thgir dekan er'uoY"
",ti od elpoep snosaer fo ytnelp era ereht …lleW"
.ngis eht ot ffo thgir detcere ngis eht deciton yllanif dna
,ydob s'werdnA ssorca dedilg dniw eltneg ehT
.ralloc eht ta pmad teg ot gnitrats ydaerla saw trihs sih taht timda ot dah werdnA nevE
tlahpsa tol gnikrap toh eht ssorca gnigdurt retfA
.gninosaer ”od tsuj I“
,god drawnwod laretil eht ta gnitniop ,dednamirper eh
"?uoy od ,snub detsaot tnaw t'noD"
,icreP nwonk dah eh sa gnol sa rof torrap eht nwonk t’ndah eh elihw dnA
"?riah ruoy hguorht gniwolb dniw eht evah ot sleef ti gnieerf woh wonk uoY"
,yesreJ weN ,hcaeB nosinnuG naht rehto enon saw ralucitrap ni noitacol ehT
,yas ot sseldeen ,dnA
.ereirred reh ffo wohs ot gniunitnoc
…icreP etacol ot kert rieht deunitnoc oud eht ,delttes tahT
…tsidun a er'uoy oS"
,flesmih dednefed eugirtaP
,kramer s'naiva eht draeh dah icreP fI
,revol eninac sih rof tuokool eht no seye sih dah werdnA elihW
,elpmis a erofeb ton tub
.dekan saw draugefil eht neve ,kceh
tnemtnioppasid kcom ni dias werdnA ",emahs a tahW"
"?ay od ,gnitiaw reh peek annaw t'noD .werdnA ,no emoC"
.sreogytrap rehto eht yb deifitcejbo dna delgo eb ot meht gniwolla dna
.noitcerid s’taP ot revo daeh sih denrut werdnA
,no deirrac yeht ,sselehtenoN
.esnes yna ekam t'ndid esnopser s'torrap ehT
.ezeerb ytlas eht gnola dedilg liat sih sa dewolf dna debbe srehtaefliat siH
gnitfihs kcab sih no thgiew eht leef dluoc eH
,tlef eh elbatrofmocnu erom eht ,taht no detod eh erom eht dna
esop s'naiva eht
.ruoh tsap eht ni emit driht eht rof derewsna mih ot txen naiva neerg eht
ffo trihs sih detfil werdnA
.yadot trihs a htiw rehtob neve t'ndid I yhw s'tahT
tnemom yrev taht ta saw tI
!pu dewohs owt uoy emit tuobA"
".esiwrehto ydob ruoy gnirevoc boj hguoroht a od ot erus neeb ev'dluow I"
",trihs a gniraew ton dnatsrednu I os ,yakO"
,tuo detniop naiva eht
.dereehc yllacitsaisuhtne icreP
".emoh ta dekan nettog tsuj ev'dluoc ew tub ,dum eht ni kcits a eb ot toN"
",hcaeb edun a ot su koot ehs ,esruoc fO"
"!aedi on evah I !uoy dlot I ,werdnA"
,yrctuo eht fo noitcerid eht ni sdaeh rieht gninnipS
".neht yakO"  ".doog m'I ,haN"
"…semitemos tsinoitibihxe na fo tib a eb nac I ,timda I ,yakO"
,neercsnus fo elttob eht no kcab pac eht gnippoP  "…fo gnikaepS
.ylevitcepser ,elddufeByssaB@
,delevram naiva eht ",haoW"
.eldnah sti pu dekcip dna relooc eht ot revo detturts taP
taog niatnuom eht ot tnerappa ylgnisaercni emaceb ti
.elcatceps hcus on saw ereht ,revewoh ,ereH
,pot knat sih fo sparts eht ta gnigguT
sdik egelloc fo eireganem a
".taht yas dluow uoy esruoc fo
.zzaj taht lla dna ffo wohs ot yxes s'ti dna oobat s'ti ekiL
.kcapkcab eht ni ti
tnemtrapa denoitidnoc-ria sih fo eveirper eht rof degnol taog eht
"!doog lla s'ediskcaB"
,deilper taP ",evah dluoc eW"
eb ot deraeppa ,sehciwdnas dekcap-erp eht no nwod gniwohc
,detats werdnA ",thgir llA"
em gnillet tpek ehS
hcaeb lanoitpo-gnihtolc a ot og dluow toidi na ylnO“
.detuohs eciov ffo raf os ton a "!drib dekan ,yeH"
,dias eh sa doog sa leef t'ndid ti fi neve ,lleW
.ytnuoC kloffuS ni esuoh s'taP morf yawa rehtraf neve dna
,edistuo saw ti sa ecin sA
,derewsna eh ",won deipuccoerp elttil a m'I tub ,dluow I"
elbissop yna naht taeh eht ot eud ylekil erom saw siht taht tuo derugif yllautneve werdnA
".ereh tog ehs tnemom eht tius reh dehctid ylbaborp icreP sediseB
.rehtie truh t'ndid sredluohs sih ot gnikcits
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.retaw tlas eht morf gnituohs
".hcaeb cilbup a si sihT"
"!eldoop dekan ,yeH"
.erofeb hcaeb lanoitpo-gnihtolc reporp a ot neeb reven ev'I"
yks eht ot pu smra sih dehcterts eh
.teknalb eht no mih ediseb dnal ti tel dna
,dnah ni relooc dna lewoT
.emas eht tlef taP teb ot gnilliw saw dna
"!tnereffid yletelpmoc s'tI
.8 fo xedni VU a dna seerged ytenin fo hgih a rof dellac tsacerof eht ,lla retfA
,noitseuq ni drib erab ehT
".noos laer noitacilppa dnoces a deen ll'I ebyaM"
"?deen uoy did tahw oS"
ralucitrap ni slaudividni esoht tub ,srehto wef a erew erehT
.ti gniees tuohtiw ti dessap eh rednow on saw ti os ,ngis llams ylriaf a saw tI
,tlah a ot werdnA thguorb sdrow tsal s'eugirtaP
"?krow morf emoh tog uoy tnemom eht ffo stnap ruoy nekat reven ev'uoY"  "?llew sa stnap tub"
"!meid gnikcuf epraC"
.eye sih hctac ot deneppah
.yad hcaeb a gnivah fo aedi s’icreP revol lautum rieht saw tI
.dnah sih ni sehciwdnas eht ot gninoitom
,tiftuo fo egnahc sih nopu devorpmi dah doom s'dneirf sih dalg saw taog ehT
,eugra ot toh oot saw ti dias uoy nehw ,gnikniht tsuj saw I"
"…nalp ruoy s'taht fI"
,sriahc hcaeb rieht ni gnihtabnus
,efil tseb sih gnivil
",enod kcab eht deen tsuJ"
,yllacificeps eroM
,hgis ylno dluoc taP
,dekoj eh "?erugif yxes siht peek I kniht uoy od woh
.meht dnuora seirots trohs gnitirw dna snaginanehs dekan fo stros rehto dna msinoitibihxe
tuP"  "?sruoy ot deneppah tahw ksa I erad dnA"
.mohtaf dluoc eh tcilfnoc lanretni
,ttub eht no kcams thgil a reh gnivig dna kcab s'icreP fo ffo sdnah sih gnitfil
,pu sbmuht a htiw werdnA ot gninrut ,dedda eh ",llitS"
".gnihton s'ti ,ylsuoireS"
.em romuh tsuJ"  "?tahw yhW"
,htiw railimaf saw eh erusaelp a saw tI
…ekil ,haeY"  "?reifmoC"
trapa deppir gnieb orclev fo dnuos elbaeciton eht raeh dluoc taog niatnuom eht ,mih dniheB
.dehcuot ti reverehw spmubesoog gnivael dna mrof sih fo hcni yreve gnigguh
dekan yllausac gnieb taht dezilaer I tnemom eht ecniS"
.noitnetta rieht barg ot gnituohs dna gnivaw
.wot ni relooc eht htiw deklaw taP elihw
.gnippiznu sreppiz dna
,denialpmoc ehs "!yeH"
,detats icreP ",kcab ym teg ot ydobemos deen I
,desopxe mottob dna stib erab sih htiw nevE
".stnap ruoy ni ti peek t'nac owt uoy esuaceb tsuj tuo dekcik gnitteg no gninnalp ton m'I"
,noinapmoc dehtolc sih ta kcab gnikool dna gnippots yllanif
.AMoM eht ni derutaef sgnitniap fo mih dednimer tnemom taht ni arua tnednecsnart dna
.did ehs sa hcum sa dekan gnieb deyojne dah ohw ydobemos dnuof icreP dalg sselehtenon saw eh
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,eugirtaP yb
,naf reccos yzarc a ekil romalc ot deunitnoc eninac eht sA
.retal sdnoces wef a gnilggig detrats eugirtaP litnu si taht
.edit eht drawot spets tsrif sih koot eh sa dias eh ",icreP nioj annog m'I kniht I"  .anavrin sa ti ot derrefer taP yhw dootsrednu werdnA
.aedi eht ot timmoc ot saw eh gnilliw woh erus yltcaxe t’nsaw taog eht
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.yawyna thgit adnik saw tI
,dnim ot emac esarhp a ,gurhs a htiW
.dehcrep saw icreP erehw ot yaw sih edam ruomatem deroloc-tnim eht
nosinu ni seye rieht dellor sgodnroh owt ehT
.deksa werdnA "?tahW"
,ot gniog erew yeht hcaeb hcihw meht dlot icreP ecno ,revewoH
,noitulos suoivbo na saw ereht
".yesreJ gnikcuf ot yaw eht lla evird ot evah t'ndid ew ,hcaeb eht ot og ot detnaw icreP fI" ,denialpmoc werdnA
.deprah werdnA "?hguoht yhw tuB"
.nwodbur denoihsaf-dlo doog a icreP evig ot deraperp dna kcolbnus eht debbarg dah werdnA
.ytilatnem ralimis a evah ot deneppah icreP ,niaga nehT
,seye sih gnillor ,esnopser ni dehgis werdnA ,derewsnanU
,eh taht seitirailucep detrevrep laudividni eseht saw ti ,gnihtyna fi dnA
ytrap yalp deleuf-yllauxes a fo gnittes eht neewteb ecnereffid esnemmi na saw ereht ,niaga nehT
,sdrow ruof esoht gnidaer retfa yletaidemmI
,hgU"  ”.etsaw ot og ytinutroppo eht tel t'ndluoC" ,deggurhs eH
,ecnatsid eht ni erugif teloiv dna kcalb eht fo erawa edam saw oud eht ,ytilaer ot kcab thguorB
.hcaeb lanoitpo-gnihtolc a dna
..."  .tnemom eht gnicarbme
kcaskcur deffuts-yrossecca rieht otno gnidloh werdnA htiw
.tnetnoc s'traeh sih ot nwod wohc ot nageb eh ,os dnA
".yrgnuh teg ew erofeb gnihtyreve tae t'nod tsuJ"
.taP ot revo ecnalg yllanoisacco dluow eh
,elpoep eht lla tuohtiw neve dnA
"!FFUTS RUOY WOHS !YBAB ,FFO TI EKAT"
,kcap s'eanirpac eht ni kcab ti tup
,srentrap evissimbus rieht gnippirts fo tuo wohs a ekam dluow smod eht woh dellacer eh
,tseuqer s'eldoop eht rep ,elihwnaeM
.hcaeb eht fo senud ydnas
".reifmoc tsuj s'ti ,yltsenoh
.rehtaew roodtuo tcefrep eht morf yrc raf a llits saw ti
.elucylop euqinu a hcus meht fo eerht eht edam taht
.detcerroc drib eht
.nwod delttes yeht sa
"?srehto eht lla revo hcaeb siht esohc ehs yhw uoy llet t'ndid ylsuoires icreP gniyas er’uoy ,taP oS"  eugirtaP yb ”nosinnuG ta dekaN gnitteG“   yojne esaelP
,seenk sih dehcaer ti litnu
.eugolaid desarhparap eht thgilhgih ot setouq-ria gnikam
.tuo skcid wef a ees ot tcepxe ton dna
”nosinnuG ta dekaN gnitteG“
,elddufeByssaB yb edam tra yb deripsni saw dna
".tuo flesruoy kconK"