!yaw on ,tahW“   ”.og
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.niaga elzzum ym revo delruc dnah a htiw esolc em gnidloh reteP ,eb nac sa
.revo em denoitom dna dehsuh saw reteP
.redluohs ym no pals drah a dna krims a htiw dias nivaG ”,dloc
.elims a htiw daeh ym no tah dezisrevo na gnittup
sdrawkcab delbmuts terref dlo ehT
”!?GNIOD OWT UOY ERA TAHW  !!!YREVA DNA NIVAG YEH“
.pu tsif sih htiw dnuora gnilrihw nivaG
,nivaG ,yob etoyoc rellat ehT
.sdrawretfa yltrohs yawa gniklaw
.elihw a rof ykcits saw tah s’reteP hcihw retfa
)!yrots eht gnillet yob eht htiw eugra t’nod(
”.ti etah I yas t’nac I tuB  .reveN“
.rekihhctiH flowereW
”?nomed suoredrum a otni snrut eh fi
evaH“ .enot gnimlac a htiw dias reteP ”,nomiS ,xaleR“
,pip ,hcus dna reporp etiuq ni nekat eb dluoc uoy ,yas od I“
,draeh ew lla saw ”!enoG“
,cinap a ni tuoba dekool I
yad a no dnA  !thguac su tog evah dluoc uoY“ :tsrif
.tnenitnoc wen elohw a no
dna yawyna seloh fo lluf saw ti ecnis ,esruoc fo ,dnim t’ndid I
.denediw seye s’eteP
.pu desiar smra ym
sihT“   ”.yrevA dna nivaG htiw enog adluohs ew ebyam
,hguone erus dna ,teerts eht otni dna edistuo dereep I
.dah ew tnemeticxe eht gniyojne saw I tub ,derit dna ytaews saw I
,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb
.setib yzal gnikat dna gniwehc ylwols
.rellik dedoolb-dloc a si ziF naM dlO taht“
.su fo owt eht revo depard saw dnuof dah ew taoc eht dna
”,oot ,rehtorb sih…ddo tsuj s’eH“
.ereht gnidnats saw nam llat yrev a daetsni tub
,ylteiuq gnikaeps dna resolc ni gninael ,deunitnoc nivaG
.delwocs eh ,gnilggig ,su was eh nehW
,llaw kcirb a otni demmals tsomla dna deddiks em fo tnorf ni yob flow eht sa detuohs I
?gnorw gnieb pu dne uoy tub gnorw eb t’ndluoc uoy ekil leef uoy esuaceb t’nod uoy tub pots tsuj dluohs uoy wonk uoy dna gnihtemos tuoba gniklat er’uoy nehw wonk uoY
nrut…gniht…eht was I ekorb ti nehW
”?naem uoy od tahW“   ”.kaeps ot os
.tuo deffup tsehc ym
.tuo deffup tsehc sih htiw duorp dna llat doots eH
.ssenkrad eht otni dehsinav dna deyaws dna dekcilf liat sih sa dehctaw I
,gnillaf tsomla dna gniddiks ,syella dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
dna dnah sih ni orruhc a
daorb sih revo smra sih dessorc eh sa reteP ta delwocs nivaG
,yggof dna dloc saw tI
eht nO  .repap eht fo egap eritne na fo flah revoc ot hguone egral saw taht tnemesitrevda repapswen a fo tuotuc a saw tI
”.’nihton yrrow t’noD
dna dlo sraey evlewt saw I
”.snevets neve ,syaw ruof ti tilpS“
”…hu s’eH“   ”?…gnorw s’tahW“
dna sgniw tuorps ll’eH
.esolc ni em deluah dna sredluohs ym dnuora mra sih gnittup ,dias reteP ”!pleh
,deplug dna elzzum ym fo og tel dneirf ym yllaniF
.nirg yhtoot ,gib a gnihsalf ,redluohs sih revo dias reteP
”!uoy evah tahw dna oireehc pip
,ti otni nwod klaw ot denrut dna
,kcohs neddus ni depmuj woleb syob
rehtona eno tsniaga gninael erew ew dna ,gnilggig osla saw eh noos tub suoires dnuos ot gniyrt saw eH
retnuocne laitini ruO
”?ttum ,taht od ew dluow yhW“
dna etatiseh t’ndid I
.elpoep eht dehctaw dna nwod dehcuorc reteP
.desufnoc fi sa kcab pets a koot dna saw daeh s’reteP erehw nwod gnikool saw eh
a eb lliw ereht worromot dna
,raews I ,ecno dna setuor no gnikcab elbuod
.roolf eht no nwod pmur ym gnippolp ,deksa I
flow gib yrev a fo dnuos eht draeh ew su dniheB
.diputs saw sihT .enips ym pu toohs llihc a tlef I
,aedi tseb eht t’nsaw tI
ecno eH  .skcirt efink did eh wenk enoyrevE
dna…nosrep a rof hguone gib ylerab wodniw llams a
llits sa ereht tas dna dnuorg eht ot delbmut eW
”.ot nosaer doog a tog I ssel’ ereh emoc t’nod I taht ffun’ daB“  ”—ti nac dab woH
——retcarahc gniwollof eht rof tuokool eht no eB
.yltcaf-fo-rettam dias yrevA ”,neewollaH s’tI“
.eltsihw sih welb eh sa su ta detuohs eh
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.nam a saw swodahs ni dekaolC
.pit eht ta eceip llams a gnissim saw
.yltfos dias reteP
llaw eht pu delbmarcs I
hturt eht revocsid reteP dna nomiS woh tuo dnif ot
,renroc eht dnuora dna
owt ehT  .sgnul ym fo pot eht ta detuohs I
hcum os syawla saw ti tub
.smitciv sih ta gnihsals elihw
.ti ot mih taeb I tuB
”,ylduol taht maercs ot deen t’ndid uoY !nomiS“
sretcarahc suoicipsus yna rof tuokool eht no eb esaelP
”.ytic eht revo lla seidob daed fo not
,ecnatsid eht otni raeppasid namow eht gnihctaw retfa ,erugif ehT
sgniRsuirebiT yb
”!tuctrohs a wonk I ,em wolloF“
,redrum etacidni ot kcen ym ssorca enil a werd I nehW
.setatS detinU eht ot revo yaw elohw eht nwod daeh ym peek ot deganam dah dna
”!ffo tuc sliat ruo teg ’nog eW“
srenroc dednuor eW
,ssenkrad eht otni ylf
.knilb dluoc uoy naht rekciuq moor denodnaba eht edisni dna reddal eht pu
gnidliub a fo edis eht no epacse erif eht pu gniyrrucs neht dna ,stoidi ekil selddup hguorht gnidils
.ti ekil gnihtyna nees reven dah I
htiw dluoc I sa llat sa )tas ro(
.su gniwollof gnihtemos gniraeh
?sseug I ,nwod sgniht gnittap htiw od ot gnihtemoS  .onnuI“
”?ere’ em tnaw dluow ohw os ,em ekil plehw a detnaw nodnoL dlo-ylloj ni eno oN“  .ylevissimsid dnah a devaw I
.no gniog saw tahw wenk eh taht esolc oot ton tub
…hehE“  .dnah sih htiw eson sih gnipiw
,emit eno ta ,em dlot dah reteP
”?ziF nam dlo ’niwollof uoy yhW“
xof kcalb a—saw eh ereht
.renroc eht dnuora dereep dna resolc dehcuorc dna dehgis I
.tsniaga dehcuorc llits saw I erehw renroc eht drawot kcab gnippils neht dna gnippots
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ti sa sredluohs sti gnikahs nageb
,htuoy dehsirevopmi rehto yna naht tnereffid on
”eehT raebroF dialnU tsohG“
.drah gniplug ,deksa I
”,nomiS ,yaS“   .reteP saw oS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.loof a ekil rae ot rae morf dennirg yrevA
,retfa gnol oot ton egakcap a htiw tuo emac dna pohs a otni dehsinav eH
.deye ediw ,gnirats saw yrevA dna delworg nivaG
,nattahnaM fo snezitic dooG  !NOITNETTA  —————————————————  :sdrow gniwollof eht erew htaenrednu thgir dna—selcinorhC llebssorC—repapswen eht fo eman eht saw tuotuc eht fo pot
”,kaolc sih rednu hsalf gnihtemos was I“  .pu denethgiarts
”.shtuom ruo nar ew taht tegrof su tel reven lliw nivaG dna yrevA ,ti teg t’nac ew fi dna
er’uoy erehw ees dluohs uoY !yO“
,yarG reteP retcarahc tseug laicepS htiW ,ztiurF dna
.pmur ym no nwod llef
.llaw gnorts yrev a gnittih
,dnah ym fo kcab eht ekil ytic eht wenk I
denodnaba gnol saw tI
,srednepsus sih yb mih debbarg dna tuo dehcaer I
elbuort otni su teg ot woh wenk osla eH  .)syawla ton(
,neewollaH no ,tuB
.regnol elihw elttil a rof gniticxe oot teg t’ndluow sgniht dna yaddim llits saw tI
.doog on su od dluow
,secalp modnar ot gniog eb ot demees
.ti eta eh elihw evissap gnikool
”.eivvaG ,uoy morf ’ninihw fo kcil a raeh annaw t’nod I drawer eht teg dna mih hctac ew nehw tuB  !eniF“
,thgir neht ,tfel dekool ew dna dne no doots ruf ruO
.netfo ot neeb t’ndah I taht ytic eht fo trap a ni erew ew dna tes gnol dah nus eht won yB
.wodniw eht otni flesmih deluah dna pu tpael eH
.gnikahs saw reteP
.gninworf ,dias dneirf ym ”?tahW“
.yrgna enoemos fo lworg eht dna
.yracs dekool evah tsum eW
dah tI  .htmraw fo tnemom a flesym gnivig ,sdap eht ssorca ria mraw welb
”!nomiS nom’C  ?yadot ekil
.sseug s’enoyna saw taht dnoyeb did xof taht tahw tuB
!dlaregziF  !xof taht s’tI“
.thgin eht hguorht decreip taht maercs llirhs a ni denepo htuom reh
.dlaregziF dniheb raf ylbirret t’nerew
-----------—   ”!niw eninac tseb eht yam tuB“
.su drawot gninnur teef fo dnuos eht draeh eW
kcaJ deleeH gnirpS :emaN
.doohrobhgien eht morf sruo fo sdneirf owt erew yrevA dna nivaG
dna teerts cilbup eht otno kcab tog ew sa xaler ot gnitrats saw I
ti taeper ohw esoht fi erac ton seod tI
,wodniw eht edistuo spetstoof draeh eW
:roloC ruF xoF :seicepS
.sgnidliub emos fo foor eht ssorca depmuj eh
htiw dna elpoep tsom naht rellat erew ew rehtegoT
”eehT raebroF dialnU tsohG“
,nar dna liat denrut eW
,did ehs sa tub ,saw ti tahw retsiger ot dnoces a dedeen ehS
stekcop sih otni gud yrevA
”.reteP ,yaw gnimrahc a ni ton dna yllis dnuos uoY  !ti tiuQ“
.od yeht tahw ton wonk
.yella eht nwod mih dael ot detrats dna dnah s’reteP koot I
dna nwod gnillaf yrevA
”.emit on ni uoy tpoda ot ylimaf xof ecin a dnif ylbaborp dluoc uoy ,uoy ekil dik A“  .dias eh
,rehtona eno gnilkcat yllufyalp noos erew eW
”.seitrap kcolb gnirud tpecxe teiuq
.noitatiseh ni plug em edam tI
,neewollaH si ,ts13 rebotcO
.daeh ym no tah dezisrevo ym dexif I  .toidi
.noitcerid ni egnahc eht gnisu
.egar fo lrans a dna skcirb eht ssorca swalc fo dnuos eht saw erehT
.ti deretnuocne ehs nehw renroc eht dnuora denrut tsuj dah ,seitxis reh ni ylgnimees ,terref A   .2 fo 1 traP ,ztiurF & sgniR suirebiT yb
”!ria eht ni efink taht gnissot dna ’niltsihw s’eH
taht dna ,seno neerg ym ot desoppo sa seye wolley-nedlog dah eh taht saw tsom eht trapa su dehsiugnitsid tahw tub ,em ekil
gnidliub a sa llat sa pael ot elba eb ot deveileb neeb sah tcepsuS   .sregnif dedalb
emit txen ni enuT
.ecnis reve elbarapesni neeb dah eW
.gnihgual llits ,kcab detuohs reteP
eh…tsrif ta dnif ot drah neeb dah eH
ot evah t’nod uoY“
.nerraw a ni tibbar a ekil yaw sih wenk ohw reteP saw ti tub
,deraeppa reteP nehw syob redlo emos wollof ot tuoba tsuj
”,wonk uoy ,em htiw dnuor’ kcits syawla
.yob rellat eht ta pu dekool I
dna delley I ”!og s’teL“
”—ot ecalp doog a fo wonk uoy oD  .llew os
.tsehc ym ni gnidduht traeh
.dloc yrev gnieb tnaem taht dna gnimoc saw retniw won tub shtnom rof mraw dna ecin neeb
a hctac t’ndluoc owt uoY“
peels ot gniog ma I“
.flesmih neht dna tsrif nwod em gnipleh reteP
.em naht reggib gnieb mih fo eutriv yb tsuj gninniw reteP esruoc fo dna
”…skcub ytfiF“  —————————————————  .srallod 05 $ fo
”,reteP ,yella krad siht ekil t’noD“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT no
.gniknird ot yaw rieht no llew rehtar ro
.dnik emos fo yrotcaf dlo na ekil dekool tI
eno on dna ,starb teerts erew ew tub
.gninnur tpek dna
erew dna gnidliub eht fo edis eht ot revo deirruh ylkciuq—
.smra sih dehcterts dna roolf eht morf pu tog reteP
.stsif sih derewol dna dehgis nivaG
.flesti lleh fo shtped eht morF  .nomed a s’eH“
.seye der gniwolg htiw
.swalc latem eht saw tuo doots yllaer tahW
.taerT ro kcirT esruoc fo dnA
,syob owt fo esac eht ni sA
.demees ti ytic eht otni gnidaeh ton saw dlaregziF .rM  .erom emos nwod dekool I
renroc eht denrut nomed
er’yehT  .hcum mih ot deklat reven I
.elttob a tih toof ym tub kcab dellup I
.seye s’dneirf ym otni gnikool ,deredduhs I
,edisni eht morf erugif eht fo taoc gnol eht denepo I sa dias I ”!thgis a tahW“
eerf rof skrow eh yas elpoep
.yawyella eht ni doots dna lleh morf eerf tsrub dah nomed a ekil saw tI
spets yvaeh fo dnuos eht yb dewollof
.hguone tsuj saw ti ,sgniht elttil ynniks gnieb su
.ees uoy dnuob mih speek ,mih no esruc a sah ’rehtorb‘
.eye ym fo renroc eht fo tuo tnemevom was I nehw gnidliub eht otni repeed og dna yawa nrut ot tuoba saw I
.em hguorht dewolf daerd gnisimorpmocnu fo gnileef taht dne daed a ot emac ew nehW
”…sgniht gniees tsuj era ylbaborp uoy ,sediseB“
eid ot gniraperp saw I
.ruoh siht ta neve efil fo esion thgil eht gniraeh
.nees fi hcaorppa ton oD
.elzzum sih dnuora sdnah sih deppuc eh sa derettum reteP
,taht dna siht dniheb gnidih ,daor eht nwod gnikaens erew yeht…yob etoyoc ykcots a dna buc flow ynit a saw tI
.ydal dlo desirprus a hcus morf tcepxe dluow eno sdnuos gnirettit eht lla gnikam
gnirpS…ziF ton s’ti…tuB  .ereht s’eH“
”!taht rof ecin oot s’eH  !yaw oN“
.gnitaeb straeh ruo raeh dluoc I teiuq os saw tI
,sgnidnuorrus ruo fo ssenmid eht ni snoom lluf owt ekil dekool taht sih fo seye nedlog esoht htiw em ta nwod derats eH
,sgniht lla fo ,htiw ereht gnidnatS .ziF saw tI   ”—
.taoc dedracsid a debbarg dna og em tel reteP nehw
”!naem uoy ,htaed ot flah tsomla reh deracS“   .evolg a ekil
,t’ndid I tahw was eH  .evarb saw ,hguoht ,reteP
?ffo yad eht evah eh diD
.emag riaf saw enoyreve ,yadot ekil yad a no tub ,seidal dlo no gnikcip eb t’ndluow ew yllamroN
,flowcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
sa em woleb morf dias reteP dneirf ym
saw I  .nosrep elgnis a wonk t’ndid osla I
.enips ym pu srevihs sdnes llits
.yenom hcum os nees reven dah I
,yretsym ni dekaolc erugif llat gniyfirroh a doots reh fo tnorf nI
.renroc txen eht ot pu gnikaens erew eW
ytic eht otni repeed tnew eh wenk eW
,yob a detcepxe dah gniht ehT  !dekrow tI
dna srednepsus sih dexif dna ffo trihs sih detsud eH
,knurd erew yehT
?gnaG kcoS kcalB eht ,wonk uoY“
,dnah sih morf derettilg snolat ekil rozar ,prahs ,gnoL
.ziF .rM wollof ot dediced dah eW
,flowcaM boR yb daeR   .ppoH etaN / sicoV sumoD yb
.llits eb ot dah I .teiuq eb ot dah I
.dnegel ytic a saw dlaregziF .rM
:ecnaraeppA  deR :roloC eyE
erusaert dnif dna erolpxe ot secalp wen ,seloh yedih dna syawegassap wen gnidnif syawla saw eH
”!ttum on t’nia I“  ”!STTUM NMAD UOY“
no dna dnik emos fo kaolc a ni depparw erew sredluohs siH
kcalB eb ot deveileB
latem fo edam eb ot demees ecaf siH
.pots t’ndid llits eW
.llew sa taoc sih ni
.teerts eht otni nwod dna tuo gnireep
.elzzum ym revo dnah sih tup eh tub
.yawa su evig I tsel dluoc I sa ydaets sa flesym dloh ot dah I
.enog saw eh niatrec erew ew litnu setunim erom wef a rof ecalp ni deniamer eW
”.evisnepxe dekool tI“ .denialpxe eh
,skcirb eht tsniaga em mals dna kcab em llup reteP tlef I  !?em nees ti saH
s’tel…nomiS…kcaJ deleeH
mih tif yllautca tah sih hguoht ,enim ekil hcum tah a dna ruf yarg emosdnah htiw flow A
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.heh-heH  .naem I tahw wonk uoy fi ,smitciv sih htiw syalp osla eH
.I dna reteP ot tuo dleh eH
”.eciffo tnetap eht ta skrow ohw eno ehT“  .deunitnoc reteP
eht…nam eht nehW
.yaled yna tuohtiw derewsna I ”!seY“
.enog gnol erew syad esohT  .rehtona eno detah dna sthgif fo tol a otni nettog dah etoyoc eht dna eh
”?ti fo tuo teg t’ndluoc ew elbuort hcum os ni su tog reve I
.gnidliub krad eht otni dellup saw dna
yella eht ni tfel saw I tnemom a roF
desaet dneirf ym ”,drawoc uoY“   ”.tsrif og uoY“
cirbaf fo gnilffuhs eht
.sdrawkcab dereggats kcaJ sa niap fo naorg a draeh I
na ekil rae ot rae morf gninnirg dna taoc dezisrevo eht gniraew llits saw I
.ria fo shtaerb gib nwod deplug eh sa
,tahW“  ”?ereh emac uoy nehw
,wodniw eht ot revo deklaw eh
.kroY weN s’ti ,naem I“
.erehwyreve saw dloc dna wedlim fo llems eht—
.snoitcerid tnereffid gniog deirt ew sa
.yob rellat eht ot pu derepsihw I
!siht htrow saw yenom fo tnuoma oN
.dehcterts dna teef nwo ym otno pu tog dna seye ym dellor I
”?yako ,ti tuoba ’niklat trats ew erofeb ereh fo tuo teg s’teL“
ll’eW“  …ziF hctac dluoc yeht fI
.mrof sih gnittih thgilnoom fo smaeb emos htiw ssenkrad eht ni doots eH
.seitinaforp fo ynatil a yb dewolloF
ti yad siht ot dna was I tahw ees ot tcepxe ton did I  .em saw tahT
dna elzzum ym ot pu sdnah ym thguorb I sa nodnoL fo em dednimer tI
yvaeh gnihtaerb ym
,elzzum sih fo edis eht fo tuo gnillol eugnot sih ,detnap reteP
”eehT raebroF dialnU tsohG“   yojne esaelP
daor eht nwod ,yldeirruh ,nar dna ylkciuq pu tog ehS
yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT morf
,tsud eht dna trid eht ni dnuora gnillor
dna dekrep rae s’reteP  .gniltsihw
.pih sih no htaehs eht otni dekcut ti ees dluoc ew tub ,gniworht-efink erom on
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
sih esuaceb latrom raluger a ekil stca ylno eH
”.hguoht ,hcum yas t’nseod eH“
!?mih eracs dna yrt ot gniog yllaer erew eW
,snogaw dekrap rednu gnikcud ,snac hsart revo gnipmuj ,drah nar eW  !nuf
.ecilop eht fo mrofinu psirc eht gniraew flow eht was dna
”.ecnedive fo kcil a teg t’ndid eW ?daeh ruoy tih uoY“
.gnikrims ,nivaG ta pu deralg dna reteP fo tnorf ni yaw ym dehsup I
.pmur reh no thgir llef dna
”.ay rof gniog tnecca taht evah od uoy ,lleW“
.daeh sti
.sraey wef tsap eseht stnedicca etanutrofnu ynam dah evah ew
,yadirF siht elihw taht desivda eb esaelp
rae thgir ytniop sih fo pit eht
yeht…nees eb ot ton gniyrt
.rehto hcae tub gnihtyna deen t’ndid ohw snihcru teerts fo riap A
.taoc sih rednu revihs yob a ekam ot hguone
,daeh s’reteP no elppa na otni thgir efink a werht
”.deen ew tahw tog I kniht I emit siht…lleW“  .deggurhs flow ehT
.tah pot a saw daeh sih
.koot ziF renroc yna gninrut erofeb
.ffo deppils tekcaj eht dna kcab llaf smra ym tel I
thgit dna ecin pu dekcut saw reteP
redluohs s’dneirf tseb ym no detaes saw I  .ti morf tuo gnikeep
”!ni deggard tac eht tahw kool ,lleW“
.sregnif sih delggiw eh sa thgil eht gnihctac
.repap fo teehs pu dellor a tuo dellup dna
.pu dekool dna denaorg I
,yad lla enog semitemos saw dna
”?ekolb naciremA na htiw elbuort otni ’nitteg naem uoy
.hcnelcnu ot trats yllanif tsehc ym tlef I
.dehca seilleb ruo litnu gnihgual dna
prahs-rozar dna epac a htiw kcalB
.mih htiw emoc dluohs I taht dna ,nwot ni yrekab tsednik ,tsetseb eht wenk eh taht dias eH
”.nomiS ,nwot fo edis dab eht si sihT“
,wodniw eht hguorht tuo kcab gnippils erew eW
nwod dna pu gnivaeh tsehc niht sih ,detnap dna kcab sih otno llef reteP
erugif deksam siht fo stuobaerehw eht ot noitamrofni yna htiw enoynA
.deeps kcenkaerb ta yawyella eht nwod gninnur
srekcart trepxe erew I dna reteP yllufknahT
.yawrednu ydaerla si lautir tnazingocni esohw
.teerts eht no peels t’ndid ohw evil dluow enoemos ecalpyna morf raf erew ew dna sgnidliub redlo erew esehT
.ffo bmilc em tel dna nwod dehcuorc eh
.reteP ,evil ll’ehs ,wA“
!mitciv sselpah sti evoba gnimool
.yralubatsnoc lacol ruoy ot ddo gnihtyna troper dna
.gniod erew ew tahw dna erehw skcil owt erac dluow
.efink sih gnissot dna gniltsihw
.em dniheb liat ym gnihsiws ,sdnah ym no pu tas I
.dehcatta gninaem a htiw semoc taht ,detaeper noitca
.seigiffe devrac dnah dethgil eht ,sksam ehT .evE swollaH llA fo yadiloh eht ot ytilauq lautir a si erehT
.rethgual otni tsrub
.dnuora denrut I dna kcaJ deleeH gnirpS htiw
.reteP ot pu derepsihw I ”,sgnag eht rof skrow eh draeh I“
…nwod tneb neht dna em no ti tup eH
”!reteP ,diputs si
dekoops elttil a dekool llits ohw—yrevA ,yob flow retrohs eht dna
.ti dnuora dereep dna renroc a ta deppots ew sa gnihctiwt liat ,dnuora gnikool saw reteP
.deggurhs flow ehT   ”?tnetap a s’tahW“
dna enoemos otni depmub I nehw ffo tuc saw ecnetnes ehT
)ton naht netfo erom(
.mih ot txen dial dna nwod deppolf I
”.em fo htaed eht eb annog er’uoy ,sttum uoy ,raews I“
fo nrettap a ylerem si ,lla retfa ,lautir tuB
.yad yretniw dloc eno skcod eht raen gnirednaw em dnuof dah reteP ,yrots bos a fo hcum oot tuohtiW
.kcab daeh sih deppans dna ylfeirb renroc eht dnuora dereep neht eH  .deplug flow ehT
.ecaf sti otni dluoc I sa drah sa toof ym demmals
stnemom wef a tiaw dna esolc wollof ,nalp elpmis yrev a gniwollof neeb dah eW
”.ruof naht yaw owt drawer eht tilps ot retteB“  .tsehc
mih no eye na peek ot hguone esolc yats ot elba erew ew dna
.esion hcum oot ekam dluow I did I fi taht wenk I tub ,shtaerb peed ekat ot detnaw I
.reppoc a fo eltsihw llircs eht yb ffo tuc saw ecnetnes s’dneirf yM  ”—dluohs ew ,reteP“
nodnoL gnivael pihs a draoba kcuns dah I
,rehtona eno otni gnipmub tsrif ta
mih ot esolc eb ot tnaw uoy dluow htraE no yhw dnA“
”!ereht thgir potS  !syob uoY“
.elbatciderpnu dna neddus sa tsuj ebyam saw
.ti eveileb t’ndluoc tsomla I ylisae os hguorht dessecorp saw I
pu ekops ohw eno eht saw ,nivaG ton ,yrevA
,ziF s’eh taht foorp deen eW
draeh ew dna teef ym ot pu em depleh eH
”,romur a s’erehT“
siht ’niod eb d’uoy thguoht reve uoy“
;niht os syawla saw eH
.nameltneg reporp a ekil kcab sih dniheb mra na htiw rellat gnidnats
.ot ton drah saw ti tub ,dah I naht eromyna hgual ot ton gniyrt saw I
.dah ew tahw htiw od edam ew tub ,yrgnuh syawla erew ew
egarevel sa mih gnisu
”…wonk uoy…rieht s’eH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
,redluohs s’reteP ffo depael
.wodniw nepo na otni dna
.tsohg a nees dah eh ekil dekool reteP
doots I tuB  .I saw oS
.dnah dehctertstuo s’flow eht koot dna pu depael I  ”!nomiS !tssP“
.og dluoc ti sa raf sa nwod dekcut tah eht dna pu dellup taoc eht htiw ria eht otni detfil saw I
drawer eht ot deltitne eb lliw
.niahc oN  ?thginot tuB
’esool tuc‘ nac eh esuaceb
,tsehc sih tuo deffup neht dna dekrims reteP
!neewollaH saw yadot ,lla retfA
!kcaJ deleeH gnirpS suomafni eht dniheb
.thgilnoom eht morf teerts eht ssorca nwod maeb wodahs sih ees dluoc I
”!emit siht revir eht ni ’nipmuj t’nia I“
,gninrom ylrae eht otni llew kcab gnimoc