,nur ot gninrut dna teef ym no pu saw I  2 fo 2 traP , ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb
.reteP ta eye ym fo renroc eht fo tuo gnikool
,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb
,dnik dna selims lla si eH“
”.ti gniredisnoc llits ma I .enoyna ro uoy gnillik evoba ton ma I hguohT  .yob revelC“
.yrreP .rM ,boj eht ot noitoved ruoy ot tnematset a si cihte krow ruoY
”—ll’ew su truh ot gnihtyna od uoy fI“
.evitom roiretlu fo dnik emos dah yeht tsael ta rO
.sregnif sih deppans neht dna nihc sih deppat ziF  ”…mhU“
”!erom on srepap ruoy lles lliw eno oN“
,deneppah tahw rednow ll’edisni sdneirf ruo dna su llik uoY“
”eehT raebroF dialnU tsohG“
.etunim yna tekcos eht fo tuo pop dluoc yeht hguoht sa dekool seye s’tuR
”selcinorhC llebssorC“ ngis eht htiw gnidliub eht drawot gniklaw saw eH
,em gniliamkcalb uoy erA“
.noitasrevnoc eht tsol dah eh ngis raelc a saw ti tub ,tsaf oot ton ,niaga dnuora em nups neht tuR
”.neewollaH ekil thgin a no ro ruoh siht ta toN  .ti gnituohs
.gnihtyna od dluoc lacarac eht erofeb
spets wef a klaw si od ot deen I llA
.gnilkcuhc llits saw eH
eb ton dluoc yeht esuaceb hsinav snihcru teerts revelc owt ekam ot evah I taht dnah ym ecrof ton oD
.reteP ot kcab yllanif dna ,em neht
!tramS !oN“  ”!tnedupmI“
.lacarac detius neerg eht ees ot emit ni tsuj edistuo deppils I dna reteP
.ekatsim yb eciffo ruoy ot desserdda s’taht liam tog I taht smees tI
…emankcin eht tuoba
”.ecnedive yna evah t’nod uoY  ?ecilop eht lleT“
.nemeltneg ,uoy htiw ssenisub gniod erusaelp a saw tI“
,gnilims ,su ta dekool dna denrut tac ehT
foor eht no dnal ot elba saw eh taht
tol a denialpxe ti tuB
”,ecalpsim ot
”.neewollaH didnelps a evah uoy epoh I
,flowcaM boR yb daeR   .ppoH etaN
.llebssorC .rM ,uoy fo dnik yrev s’tahT“
,ylmlac dna ylizal ,resolc os reve
.nees reve dah I naht yenom
.srecuas sa ediw seye sih
erom…yenom fo daw a htiw tuo emac eH
.saw I naht reggib kool ot gniyrt dna ,gniralg ,ereht gnidnats saw I
.wonk uoy ,og syawla dluoc eW“  .doof oN
sgniht…won gnillik trats uoY“
gnidliub yrots-owt eht fo
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,deplug I ”,ris ,ees uoy ,lleW“
”.uoy sllet ziF tahw tub gnihtyna ta worht oN .slamina ta worht oN .elpoep ta worht oN“
.thgin neewollaH gninekrad a no
.ksed a no lwob a ni dnuof eh taht steews eht fo emos ot flesmih depleh dah eH
.regnarts a htiw noitatnorfnoc A
nosinu ni dias htob I dna dneirf ym ”,t’now eW“  ”.revE
,regittuR saw eman esohw ,xof etihw eht nehw dna
.aedi eht ta delggig reteP dna
.saw eh ohw wenk yeht thguoht dna
reteP dna nomiS ,emit tsaL
.dekrow rehtorb niwt s’ziF erehw eciffo tnetap eht ot nwod deklaw dah eW
”!drawer suoethgir a su evag eh dna ,mih ot ti denruter eW .gnir a tsol llebssorC .rM“ .kcab ym dniheb sdnah ym tup dna dennirg I ”!HO“
”.rehtie t’ndluohs uoY
kaerb uoy fo rehtie
”!wonk uoy ,klaw nac I“
”?ni em gninrut morf uoy pots ot s’tahw dnA“
erofeb eciffo na edisni neeb reven dah I
”!eman a tsuj s’tI“
.pu taht ssap t’nac I  !laem dekooc-
,trohs rof tuR ro
remraw nrut srae ym
ni ssorca emoc syawla ton dluow eno noitamrofni teg ot kli ruoy no denael netfo I
.su neewteb dekool eH
.su ot resolc deppets dna dias lacarac eht ”,yob
.eb ot thgir yna dah I naht mlac erom raf eb ot dedneterp dna delahxe dna htaerb peed a koot I
.derewsna rehtorb sih
.nruter ni gnihtemos gnitnaw tuohtiw ecin t’nerew yllareneg elpoeP
.su drawot tah sih deppit dna delims tsuj kcaJ esuaceb
.yppah oot enon dednuos kcaJ  ”?yob
reilrae yb pord ot detnaw I
psirc a tuo dellup eH
.tuR dniheb morf daeh sih gnikop
tuoba og t’ndluohs uoY“
yenom drawer rallod-ytfif eht su
.tuR ot kcab detfird ezag siH
.ffo mih gnittuc ,detuohs ziF ”!teewS“
regna ym rebmemer dna tnemeerga ruo rebmemeR
”,oot ,meht llik dluoc I“   ”…snoitseuq ksa
.pu smra sih dehcterts neht dna dias xof kcalb eht ”!dooG“
.edis eht ot daeh sih detlit ziF
.yrrow fo llihc tnatsni na tlef I dna
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,deksa ziF ”?siht ohW“
sgniRsuirebiT yb
,su ot denoitom eH
si drow ruoy ,syob ,rebmemeR“
.gnirob si ffuts sihT“
”.gniugra pots dna pu yrruh dluow yeht hsiw I
.denrut eH  .ezorf tac ehT
.kcaJ er’uoy skniht enoyreve os ti ekam nac ew tub ni uoy nrut t’nac eW“ .delworg I
”,llebssorC iacedroM .rM s’eH“
s’eH“  .su fo tnorf ni owt eht ot ti tuoba hcum oot nialpxe ot evah ot tnaw t’ndid I tub ,I saw oS
dluohs eb lliw I yrgna woh dna
”eehT raebroF dialnU tsohG“
.ecnelis fo tnemom a retfa dedda reteP  ”!puy ,puY“
.ylwols daeh sih koohs ziF   ”?llebssorC .rM“
”.ziF ,uoy ekil hcum os skool eH
!nips dluoc taht dnik eht erew esehT
rettam siht tuoba ma I suoires woh wohs ot si yenom artxe eht oS  .snaem lausu
.sdnah htob esu dluoc eh os htuom sih ni yletelpmoc orruhc eht tup dah eh was ew dnuora su denrut eh nehW  .kcab su dloh ot strihs dna srednepsus ruo yb su debbarg ziF tub
.noitautis siht ni gnidnib
nam ecin yrev a fo ynapmoc eht ni rehtie erew ew taht ekil dnA
srepmuj elbidercni era slacarac taht ,retal ,nrael dluow I
og ti tel t’ndid tac eht tub deirt reteP
kcaJ—lacarac eht
eh hcihw ,dnah devolg sih ni saw epolevne nA
”.pu hsinif ot em rof gnitiaw tsuj
.sriahc eciffo ni gnittis flesym dna reteP htob was eh nehw pu dekool eH
era…dnatsrednu t’nod I ,yrros m’I“  .truh ti
,gnilbmag tuoba gniugra ot kcab gniog erew sniwt eht elihW   ”!ti evorp
,dnuora enac sih thguorb dna dennirg—
su htiw kcab gniregnil saw rehtorb niwt derruf-kcalb siH
,desimorp revetahW
yrots s’thginoT dna
.toof ym htiw reteP degdun I
”,yas yeht sa yldaed sa er’uoy fI“
.redluohs sih revo gab regnessem sih detsioh dna dedda tuR ”,nam ecin a ton
.dnuorg eht no drah pit latem eht htiw enac sih deknilc eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.delkcuhc lacarac ehT
edistuo deppets lacarac ehT
,god.ecioveht ta
,yarG reteP retcarahc tseug laicepS htiW ,ztiurF dna
.ffo su tuc eh ”?tahW“
edam tI  .ksed a fo egde eht no tas eh sa don a htiw dias ziF ”,emosdnaH“
.tac eht ffo seye sih ekat t’ndid eh tub mih ta pu dekool I
.tekcop sih ot tsev sih morf
nopu ediced ot sruoy sniamer ,ecnalbmeser ecnahc erem si ti rehtehw ro ,tnemtcane s’lautir a hcus dessentiw evah uoy rehtehW .ti tneverp ot nevig gnireffo na dna feihcsim fo taerht deilpmi nA
.siht gniyojne saw
.lufesu yrev demees ti fo enon tub ,gnidliub siht ni ffuts hcum os—ddo saw tI
a dellac saw tac fo epyt siht taht wenk I—
.ytitnedi desiugsid A
.elat s’thginot fo noisulcnoc
ylthgit os mra ym dleh
.dnuorg eht otno dne latem eht deknilc dna enac sih fo drabbacs eht otni kcab edalb eht tup eH
”!?tahw gniod erew uoY“
srae sih no stfut elttil ynnuf eseht dah eH
.ti ekaf ot dah I tub ,gnikahs ,suovren
.pu kcab t’ndid I dna reteP ,ylbakrameR
.kcehc ot detnaw I os no thgil eht was dna pohs pu gnisolc saw I
,resolc deppets llits tac ehT
.plug a htiw dias I  ”!t’now uoY !oN“
?flesruoy fo noisrev inim a rof gnikool osla uoy erA“
.eno suovren A  .elims a htiw dias I ”!esruoc fO“
dna gniht diputs yllaer a did I oS
.ekat ot reteP rof tuo ti dleh eH
ysae…os era snihcru teertS  .melborp yksep
.ot dnetta ot ssenisub evah I“
.yella taht ni em gniwollof erew ohw syob owt eht era uoy dnA“
”?tuoba taht lla saw tahW“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.tsehc sih tuo deffup reteP
.tac gnikool-ddo ,llat a saw ereht gnidnatS
dna yltnetni derats eH
”!tsol uoy fi doog taht ton ylsuoivbo s’tI“
.seye gnitaluclac ,dloc s’nam eht htiw dekcol saw ezag siH  ”.egnahc
”!puY !daerB !raguS“  .deksa nam eht
.dennirg dna yldipar deddon eH
.pu daeh sih tlit mih gnikam
”!dnah dooG“  ”!?YHW  !?TAHW“
,kcaJ deleeH gnirpS suoiretsym eht tuoba draeh
a os gnillup dna
draH“  .liat sih fo gaw a dna elims a htiw dias ziF ”,em wollof yehT“
”.lla uoy teem ot erusaelp a saw tI
yap…uoy…uoy dna enoyna deredrum uoy tuo dnif t’nod ew sa gnol sa
.yldeticxe deddon ziF  ”!huh-hU“  ”?ziF
”!KCAJ DELEEH GNIRPS“
”?snihcru teerts pu gnikcip ,gniod uoy era tahW“
suolucidir dekool evah tsum I
”.ti kaerb uoy dluohs
.ereh ni gnihtyna hcuot t’noD“
.eciffo deroolf-elbram eht fo rodirroc eht nwod deklaw dna sriahc ruo fo tuo deppils I dna reteP
ton…enola og ot tnaw t’ndid I tub
.thgis fo tuo dna ffo deklaw neht eH  .esae htiw
teg t’now yeht nehT“
.reteP ta dekool dna deplug I  .elzzum sih fo tuo orruhc eht gnikculp ,deksa eh ”?wollof yhW“  .deyats llew nmad eW
!yzarc er’uoY ?tahW“
dna orruhc eht dehsinif eh nehw dias ziF ”,suoregnaD“
”!kcaJ deleeH gnirpS gnidnif rof
.llib 001$
.dias reteP ”,gniracs tsuj
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
?su llik ot dennalp eh erehw saw siht fi tahw—
edalb prahs gnitnilg
sksed erew erehT
tsev sih otni ti devohs dna
t’nsi kcaJ deleeH gnirpS“   .deretnuoc kcaJ
riahc eht fo kcab eht debbarg dna tuo dehcaer ohw ,tuR yb ylneddus deppots saw I
.ydnac emos teg og dnA
”!nomed uoy ,elbaresim efil ruoy ekam ll’eW“   .deralg dna
.flah ni deppans nep ehT   ”!gnilbmaG“
.dednuos su dniheb morf eciov a ”,syoB“
taht dnuora teg ot gnihtemos htiw pu emoc dluoc I erus m’I ,hO“
.kcohs kcom fo noisserpxe na htiw em ot denrut reteP   ”.ydnac
?seidob eht dih eh erehw saw siht fi tahW
.tnetap ot noitnevni na evah I nehw tneinevnoc s’ti ,edispu eht nO“
”?uoy t’nera ,srepap ruoy fo selas pu murd ot siht gniod er’uoY“
daeh revlis eht gnibbarg
,eman suoregnad a si tahT“  .deralg eH
.emoc htob uoy ,renniD“
tius neerg a gniraew saw eH
.tbuod on ,yenom fo tnuoma eht tuoba gnikniht llits saw eH
.esle gnihton tub
.seye dnik ton erew esohT
dnah eno ni enac eht debbarg
.resolc gnippets won saw ohw ,ziF ta dekool dna denrut tac ehT
’.taerT ro kcirT‘ llac ew lautir eht rof yrassecen si elttil yreV  .rekihhctiH flowereW
terces ruoy peek ew…eW“
.me’ htiw kcil eht koot uoy semitemoS
.elzzum sih fo egdirb eht debbur tuR  ”…ziF“  ”.efink
.yldeticxe deddon ziF
.yawa mra ym hcnerw ot deirt dna denaorg I ”!yeH“
”!keew eht rof gnihtyrevE  !hO“
.elims mraw a htiw dias nam eht ”,yrreP .rM ,hA“
.delbmert dna deplug reteP
.tuR drawot dednetxe
.uoY .diD .hcuM .woH“
.lio thgindim eht gninruB“
”.ytic ni tseb ,sorruhC“
.xof derruf-etihw eht retfa klaw ot detrats dna
.epolevne eht gnikat ,deddon dna delims tuR
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.mih rof elggurts a t’nsaw hgih taht gniog taht dna
dna ’selcinorhC llebssorC‘ dellac repapswen eht snwo eH“
,rennid ot su htiw gnimoc yeht erA
”.ereht sdneirf teM
.raen erew ew yrekab eht ekil sllems eh syas ziF dnA
.ksed eht ot llaf daeh sih tel yllacitamard dna denaorg xof etihw eht ”,hguuuU“   ”!doog os gnikooc tuR“
.deksa tuR ”?rehtorb raed ym
.dnuor’ dna dnuor’ dna dnuor’ tnew riahc eht sa yb ssap sniwt eht dneirf ym ees dluoc I
!repap ruoy stnaw eno on os ti ekam nac eW
”.sselmrah s’eH .ffo ssiP  ?tac hsippof ehT“   ”!kcaJ s’eH“
.suoregnad s’tI .sgniht ta sevink prahs worht ot woh sdik gnuoy gnihcaet dnuora og t’nac uoY“
”.wonk I  .sruoh rof gniwollof neeB“
reteP ta derats lacarac ehT
”.ytic eht fo tuo uoy evird ro uoy erutpac yeht erofeb su llik ll’uoy…oN
,gnillik rof nwonk
”!emoC  .rehtorb teg ew tsrif tuB
.ot gnirrefer saw eh ”sdneirf“ eht erew ew taht dootsrednu I dna
”.won tsuj litnu togrof I taht yadot yad ysub yrev a neeb s’ti tub
.meht tnorfnoc ot ydaer
sseug I ,erus ,naem I
.hteet dettirg sih hguorht
.efink worht ot nrael ot tnaw oslA  .od ot
niahc dlog taht dah eH“
.deirt I fi nialpxe t’ndluoc I sgniht fo sgniward dna sregdel dna skooB
.revo em dekool eH  .no saw I
,tnatropmi erew ”stnetap“
ti tuoba suoixna neeb dah ew yaw elohw ehT
,gniod uoy erew tahw oS“
,su ta dekool kcaJ
.eit sih dexif dna pu denethgiarts lacarac eht
.rof desu erew ”stnetap“ eseht tahw saw taht tbuod I tub ,repap fo skcats eseht lla nrub uoy fi mraw uoy peek dluoc ti ebyaM  .ti htiw kooc rO
,rood txen thgir si gnidliub eciffo sih
er’eW  ?ris ,su hcaet uoy dluoC  !haeY“
.don kciuq a htiw dias reteP  ”!oot em-
.seye dlog htiw xof kcalb eht ta deralg seye elprup htiw xof etihw A
yawa yenom eht deknay reteP   ”.niagrab ruo
yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT morf
taehw ekil deroloc ruf dna
”.elur a sa ,steews diova yllareneg I“
dna dnuorg ruo doots eW
?nwod uoy tnuh yeht elihw og su tel tsuj ll’uoy kniht uoy“ ,nageb reteP
.gniod erew ew tahw saw taht oS
”!uoy lliw rehtieN“  ”.diap
su gnikam er’yehT
wol dehcuorc eH  !eurt
lausu ekil steerts eht ni tsol teg dna yawa pils tsuj ot detnaw I
.tekcop tius sih otni dehcaer dna mra sih rednu ti dekcut eh yllaniF
.htaerb deredduhs a delahxe dna niaga drawrof deppets I
.yraw saw I ,esruoc fO  ”…haeY“
.mih ot klat t’nod uoy taht esivda I  .prahs sa eciwt dna rozar a sa yldaed sa si eh tub
”.nilbog ro tsohg yna naht reiracS“ .derepsihw eh
,foorp rof nwod mih kcart ot dediced yehT
/ sicoV sumoD yb
.kcaJ deleeH gnirpS“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,thgiarts dormar gnidnats erew eW
.gniugra detrats yeht os dnA
.nosrep ni eno was I emit tsrif eht saw ti hguohtla ”,lacarac“
eh…em gniggum t’nsaw nam
M“  ”.nwot ni eiswen yreve wonk I
.tuo emac sniwt eht dna eciffo tnetap eht ot denepo rood ehT
.su fo tnorf ni thgis eht ta yltnetni derats
.liat sih deggaw dna ria eht deffins eH
,ylkciuq dias reteP ”,mih s’tI“
.yella eht fo dne eht ta detacol
.htaerb sih rednu ylteiuq gnikaeps ,nwod dereep dna
tcepsus rieht dnif ot ylno
”.pu dexim steg liam ruo semitemos os
”!niagrab a ekam s’tel nehT“
”!woh nrael ot detnaw ew…eW“
.neewollaH lufrednow a evah sdneirf ruoy dna uoy epoh I ,yrreP .rM
.edistuo kcaJ deleeH gnirpS htiw
.nirg a htiw dias reteP ”,enoyna ta
,flowcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
”!kcaJ er’uoY !mih er’uoy dnA“
meht worht ton ot desimorp eW“  ”.suoregnad
siht…tnereffid saw siht tub ,tol a denetaerht neeb ,erofeb em no dellup efink a dah d’I ,eruS .su llik yllaeR
.enac a gniyrrac dna
.daeh sih koohs dna ksed a no koob a hguorht gnibmuht saw reteP
dna nihc s’reteP rednu ti gnittup
emoh gib a ,nomiS ,RENNID
”eehT raebroF dialnU tsohG“   yojne esaelP
.su llik ot detnaw nam sihT
.nur t’ndid uoy regnad ni erew sdneirf ruoy nehw tub ,nur ot detnaw I
”,dneirf ym ,nekatsim eb yam uoy kniht I“
.bonk rood eht fo og tel dna denworf lacarac ehT
.stnap sih ffo sdnah sih detsud
”.revE  .yarteb reven
.su neewteb teef eerht naht ssel saw eh nehw deppots dna
”.tnaw ew yenom eht
s’ti…tub enasni sdnuos wonk I gnihtemos did neht kcaJ
.yella nwod yrekab ekil llems tuB“
,eson tsniaga eson ,ecaf s’rehtorb sih ni dna
.yawa thgir ton ,tsael ta—
”!srepap ruoy yub lliw eno oN“ .delworg reteP
slicnep emos was dna reward ksed a otni dekeep I
hgih os depmuj dna…depmuj dna
teg ew dna ,terces ruoy dna skcirt ruoy peek uoY
.od ot tahw tuoba thguoht eh sa enac sih no daeh enilef revlis eht deppat dnah s’nam ehT  ”.niagrab ruo tsniaga ni em nrut ot sa suoived
”?nodrap ruoy geb I“
.esolc dna ecin mih gnipeek dna trihs sih fo snottub eht dnuora dnah eno
,reteP ta dekool tuR
.dehgual neht dna
.ffo em tuc ziF nehw htuom ym nepo ot tuoba saw I
”?yrekab a ekil llems I gniyas uoy
.rekihhctiH flowereW
:detuohs dna elzzum sih revo sdnah sih deppuc reteP
.tfahs eht morf tuo denihs
.krow ym pu hsinif I elihw nwod tis…tsuJ
retroper a sA  .detsurt
”.ecaf eht ni em gnikcik rof eno uoy ewo I
eciffo kcab eht ni erew ew daetsnI
.gnihtemos etirw ot nageb dna nep sih pu dekcip eH
”!yrekab staerT dna steewS  !teewS“
os eb uoy dluohs egnever tcepxe ot sa dettiwmid os t’nera uoy tsael tA“ .gnitalpmetnoc
.ti raew yllaer t’ndluoc uoy tub
.repap hcum os dna ,erehwyreve
,reteP htiw gnola
.dias eh lla saw ”yatS“
.ereh llits saw ohw erus t’nsaw I“
.rood eht drawot em gniggard detrats reteP dna
era…sdneirf…sih dna rehtorb ym dna krow emos gnihsinif tsuj saw I
.niwt sih ta deralg eh su was
teef sih no saw xof etihw ehT  ”!?TAHW“
,eno yb eno ,ylwols tuo emac sdrow ehT  ”?dnepS
.mra ym debbarg dna depsag reteP
,pu kcits gniklaw sih fo daeh eht detfil dna derrup eH
”!stneduts doog yllaer
.pu ti gninepo erofeb tsev sih nwod dehtooms dna pu tog tuR .ni emoc dah ew hcihw morf rood kcab eht ot emac kconk a nehw sniwt eht drawot revo kcab gniklaw erew eW
--------—    .esor nus eht erofeb su llik dluow ohw enoemos ro
”,lived eht htiw laeD“
”.reworht efink retsam a er’uoy wonk eW“
.pil reppu sih raen ruf sih no kcuts saw etalocohc fo tib A
”—dna stnemucod ym ffo pord dna
nac I  .si ti wonk I ,nomiS mih s’tI