,sdleif eltbus rieht esnes ot elba saw ehs dna tnempiuqe cinortcele htiw denil saw moor gnitarepo ehT
,ksa ot deen ew ,aluaP“
”.uoy wohs ot gnihtemos evah eW“ .kcab doots neht
.retnuoc eht otno swaperof reh werht dna sgel-
,deifsitas fi sa deddon naicinhcet ehT
,moor gnivil eht otni dettort aluaP
.ekat-elbuod a did dna deretne ehs sa dnuor decnalg ,noisivelet gnihctaw saw mum reH
.niarb fo pmul dezis-tsif a ,ydob lanigiro reh fo deniamer taht lla dewohs daeh reh ni gnidahs thgil eht
.troppus fo segassem enilno erom ynam neeb dah ereht dna
,niaga nrob neeb dah ehs erehw saw sihT
.rehtaf reh morf denrael dah ehs tibah a ,ytilautcnup reh no flesreh dedirp syawla dah ehS
;edis reh no gniyl saw ehS
,detatirri teg ot gninnigeb saw ehS ”.ton od I“
,hguorht detivni saw ehs dna nepo gnuws rood roiretni detalp-ssalg eht sa edis eht ot decnalg aluaP
.segassem rorre ytiroirp-wol gnirongi rof reh dedihc dah rotcod reh cinilc eht ot rae reh detroper dah ehs nehw
.edutingam fo sredro ynam yb ,ylevissam desaercni dah yticapac dna deeps gnitupmoc reH
.oga skeew lareves detelpmoc neeb dah ti litnu ecap laitnenopxe na ta dedeecorp dah tI
.kcits ot demees reven ti nosaer emos rof tub
.enasni yletelpmoc enog dah noitroporp hgih a devivrus ohw esoht fO
,dennalp sa ylrae setunim evif tnemtnioppa reh rof devirra gnivah ,ehs saw sA
.meht gnillortnoc ytluciffid decneirepxe ylsuoiverp dah ehs
.os did ehs sa latem no latem fo edils a saw ereht
lortap elibom no gnieb saw derebmemer ehs lla saw ti sA
,tuo ti detniop dah mum reh litnu deciton neve ton dah aluaP
,elbat eht otno reh detfil snaicinhcet eht fo enO
.ereh saw ehs nosaer eht fo trap saw tluaf ronim siht
.moor eht fo ertnec yrev eht ni elbat gnitarepo level-tsiaw elgnis a deniatnoc osla tI
,yna dah regnol on ehs ,strap lacigoloib reh rof sisylaid dedeen regnol on ehs yhw denialpxe ylniatrec tI
.dnoces yrev eht ot
,tneserp eht ot noitnetta reh denruter ehS
------------------------------------------- .esoht ot desu saw ehS
.kool a reh evag mum reH
.grobyc a ton dna tobor a yllacinhcet ,laicifitra yleritne saw ehs
tpmorP yadsruhT eht ni tnapicitrap raluger a si dna
.noitcelfni ro enot tuohtiw saw eciov citehtnys nwo s’aluaP hguoht tnecca tnasaelp a dah tsinoitpecer ehT
.ot desu teg ot deriuqer neeb dah ehs gniht rehtona tey saw tI
.nekowa tsuj dah ehs dna gninrom saw ti
.esuoh s’tnerap reh ot srotisiv fo maerts tnatsnoc a neeb dah ereht syad wef tsrif eht roF
.desoppus ehs won namuh-tsoP
.yvaeh ylgnisirprus saw ehs dna tcapmoc dna esned erew sedisni reh llams hguohtla
.noitcetorp fo sreyal suoirav etipsed
.drow tsal eht no sisahpme eht deton ehS
.esrow sgniht edam tsuj dah tub ti xif ot deirt dah dad reh stsetorp reh etipseD
”.kcuts s’ti ekil skool tI“
,derae-elggarts gnieb reh tuoba nuf derutan-doog edam dah rehtom reH
.suoenatnatsni demees dah ti reh rof tub
.dessap srehto sa sgniteerg yldneirf htiw tem ,ertaeht gnitarepo eht ot yltcerid del saw ehS
taorht reh ni tes yltbus rekaeps a morf gniussI
,desilibats evah ot smees taht hguoht
deggalf yllacitamotua neeb dah elif eht fo stnetnoc eht tub noitamrofni eht deteled yratnulov dah ehS
.yhw erus ton saw ehs hguoht
.etartsbus gnitupmoc laicifitra na otni ,mota yb mota
,dnocesorcim eht ot nwod gnol woh yltcaxe fo erawa saw ehs
.gniht laer eht t’nerew llits yeht tub etarucca ytterp erew sesnes detalumis reH
derrucco dah gnihtemos taht noitacinummoc a gniviecer ekil erom saw ti
;snoitasnes tcerid edivorp ton did ydob laicifitra reh
.ecafrus htooms eht otno skcilc eltneg htiw delttes teef dewalc reH
.sliated eht ton fi ,deniatnoc dah ti tahw wenk llits ehs os
,llec yb llec ,decalper ylbaroxeni neeb dah niarb reh fo lairetam lacigoloib eht shtnom revo
dna…gnirussaer neeb dah rotcod ehT
.dehcaorppa yeht sa ecaf s’nosrep hcae weiv ot pu kool ot dah ehs dna
.dnoces a fo noitcarf a koot ti ,deredisnoc ehS
.tneiciffe ton fi gnihton saw syawla sa cinilc eht
,siht etipsed stroper eht daer revewoh dah aluaP
.elims eniuneg dna mraw a htiw reh deteerg tsinoitpecer eht deretne ehs sA
,dedaf dah tseretni eht sgniht lla ni sa yllaudarg tuB
,tnerappa yletaidemmi saw egnahc gnikirts tsom eht tub
.daed gnieb naht retteb saw ti
,evitroppus dna citehtapmys ,tneitap naht erom neeb dah ffats cinilc eht teY
.namuh neeb dah ehs nehw yrassecen sruoh eht naht rehtar
?gnorw enog gnihtemos dah ,ngis doog a ton saw tahT
.dnah ta esolc koobeton a htiw dnuof eb yllausu nac ohw
revewoh hturt ehT
dnih reh no doots ehs erofeb ksed eht fo elbram dehsilop eht ni noitcelfer enipluv reh fo espmilg a thguac ehS  .efil reh fo tser eht rof siht ekil eb dluow ehs
,cinilc eht sdrawot ffo denrut ehs yalpsiD pU-daeH largetni reh no dekram etuor dethgil-hgih eht gniwolloF
.dehsilbatse-er neeb ton osla dah ytilibom reH
.llew reh wenk ffats eht dna
erutaretil lagel dna lacidem ,ecilop fo egaugnal lacinilc eht nI
,nwod snoitome reh denut dah yeht yhw raelc saw ti
.dnah tsrif ta ti gnicneirepxe naht rehtar
”?thgirla ,rednu uoy tup ot tuoba er’eW“
,netfo os yreve nwod gnilttorht peek ot dah ev’I dna
”.won thgir tuo gnikaerf m’I“
”gniregdor doog a rof ereh m’I ,olleH“
.yteixna level-wol rehtar spahrep tub gnidoberof etiuq ton saw tI
-------------------------------------------  …moor eht dnuora delppir feiler desuma fo hgis A
”.strap emos decalper dna sgniht wef a pu denaelc tsuj ew ,gnihtoN“ ”?deneppah tahw
…dnah reh gnidloh saw enoemos
,tnenamrep ylbacoverri dna yllanif saw reh ot derrucco dah tahw taht tnaem ti esuaceb spahreP
,lavirra reh hguorht dellac ,desuma ylraelc ,tsinoitpecer eht sa yltneitap detiaw ehS
ygolonhcet htiw delliks neeb reven dah ehs erofeb hguohtla dna syad eseht enilno saw gnihtyreve tsomla
”.kcuts si rae ym syas
.syad ylrae eht fo zzub elbigilletninu eht morf yaw gnol a emoc revewoh dah tI
noitarud trohs fo span ni nekat eb ot dednet ti hguoht ,emit eldi gnissecorp tsael ta ro ,peels deriuqer llits ehS
”?rae ym dexif uoy evaH“  ”?aluaP“
.yticapac %5 -/+ ta tes erew yeht taht detacidni
.ekorts gnirussaer lanoisacco na edis htooms reh gnivig tub sevlesmeht tsgnoma seciov wol ni gniklat
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,detcelfer ehs reh ot deneppah dah tahw htiw delggurts ehs nehw dnA
.retfa noos ro elbat gnitarepo eht no deid dah tsom
.dootsrednu yeht dias enoyreve
,seirraH nomoloS yb daer
ecivres eht retfa dedargpu neeb dah ydob reh erehw secnereffid lareves erew ereht ,detadpu ti nehT
”.ecivres a naem uoy kniht I“
.seman gnirebmemer ta doog neeb reven dah ehs
ti…eno s’ereht ,tiaw
.ecnednopserroc dna rotisiv lanoisacco eht deviecer llits ehs hguoht
.sbmil tsol ro derujni ro snagro fo tnemecalper eht devlovni sedargpu tsoM
,esruoc fo stsiaw namuH
tseretni cimedaca dna aidem esnetni eht morf reh detcetorp dah cinilc ehT
shtnom wef tsap eht revo seenk namuh htiw railimaf yllufwa emoceb dah ehs evitcepsrep wen reh morF
,noisiv reh ni esolc deraeppa ecaf deksam A
detcennoc eb ot nageb selbac suoirav ,nepo gnuws hctah ssecca na dna
.desoppus ehs noitautis eritne eht htiw gnilaed fo yaw reh saw ti
,nettogrof eb ton dluoc hguoht sgniht emoS
,trap rieht no tseretni-fles elttil a naht erom neeb dah ereht esruoc fO
”?leef uoy od woH“
,ssentrela thgirpu na ,noitisop otni nezorf saw thgir reh
.scitenrebyc decnavda fo taht ,dleif rieht ni sredael erew yehT
,ssenisub lla won erew ,scidem trap ,sreenigne trap ,ffats ehT
.rehtegot kcab tup neht dna trapa ekat dluoc eh hcihw rotcart a t’nsaw ehs ,strap ydob reh htiw gnilddif mih pots ot dah yllaer ehS
.ton did tsom ,dehcaorppa ehs sa reh detceted seno eseht tsael tA
.eye reh fo renroc eht fo tuo eciveD-evisolpxE-desivorpmI na fo hsalf eht gnihctac dna
,grobyc a otni demrofsnart neeb tsrif dah ehs nehw morf citamehcs lanretni na dewohs ti tsrif tA
.deedni aedi dab yrev a eb dluow os gniod detseggus hcihw segassem gninraw fo sdnik lla yb derevoc saw tnemges eht tub elbissecca yllacinhcet dna tneserp llits saw tI
.taht ot desu saw ehs tub
,rellevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si siht
.daeh nwo reh fo pot eht ees dluoc ehs fi sa denrut dna detsiwt aluaP
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
”?shtnom wef tsap eht revo tnereffid gnihtyna deciton uoy evah
,dessap dah sruoh eerht revo taht deton kcolc lanretni reh dna
,ot kcab og ot mrof namuh on dah ehs tnaem ti teY
”?tnereffid gnihtyna eciton t’nod uoY“ ”.enif leef I“
,xelA_cimotA emanresu eht rednu ytiniffAruF ta dnuof eb nac ehS
egrahcsid rof elbatius deredisnoc gnieb erofeb gnidliub siht ni shtnom xis tsomla tneps dah aluaP
.kcab gnihtemos gnidloh saw ehs taht detseggus sisylana sserts ecioV
.ekatsim a neeb dah tahT
devom dah lennosrep eht fo noitisop eht
.eno naht syaw erom ni euqinu saw ehs mrof-lamina ylno eht sa dna
.srood citamotua eht hguorht dna spets eht pu dettort ylthgil
enihcam sisylaid elbatrop eht eriuqer ot mees regnol on I“
ho…segassem rorre yna gniviecer ton m’I ?erus uoy erA“
;ssensuoicsnoc reh hguorht derekcilf nrecnoc fo tsohg ehT
.gnileef egnarts a htiw dellif saw ehs
,emoh ta reh rof gnitiaw neeb dah dlrow eht dnuora morf srehsiw-llew morf liam lacisyhp fo kcas savnac egral A
”enihcaM eht ni tsohG“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
,elcihev reh fo egakcerw gnikoms dna delgnat eht morf reh devomer yeht nehw tfel reh fo hcum neeb t’ndah erehT
.kcab ecnatsid luftcepser a deppets gnivah srehto eht
.maerd ot emit dah neve ton dah ehS
.detcader saw yromem reh fo noitrop eritne taht ,deneppah dah tahw fo hcum llacer ton did ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.reh evoba yltnacifingis saw ecafrus sti
,detibahni ehs mrof laicifitra eht fo esoprup lanigiro eht ot eud saw eciohc ngised ralucitrap taht rof nosaer ehT
.tsael ta ycrem a saw tahT
.efil reh evas ot stroffe etarepsed eht ni reh ot enod neeb dah tahw yltcaxe denrael dna detacol nehw suoicsnoc neeb llits dah ehs dnuof ehs
.reyolpme rieht saw hcihw ynapmoc detcartnoc-tnemnrevog eht rof yrots sseccus detbuodnu na sa detnuoc ehs
.erac reh fo egrahc ni rotcod feihc eht ot hguorht tup neeb dna
.detamerc neeb neht dah ti dna ydob lanigiro reh fo deniamer tahw no detcudnoc neeb dah metrom-tsop a
.elbissecca won saw tuo deyerg neeb dah hcihw loot citsongaid a ,dekcehc ehs mihw a nO
.daD regdaB yldduC
.tuo lairetam detnawnu tpek hcihw erusserprevo cirehpsomta eht tceted dluoc ehs dna elirets yllacinilc saw ti
”?ecnereffid a ereht sI“
.ydaer saw ehs tlef yeht litnu seitilibapac gnikrowten lanretxe reh etavitca ot ton luferac neeb dah yeht
.dnim reh otni dehsalf stluser ehT
,dehtolc dna deksam ylluf erew yeht hguohtla detceted eb dluoc hcihw ,selims gnimoclew eht etipsed dna elbat eht dnuora deyarra reh rof gnitiaw snaicinhcet xis erew erehT
.gniyl neeb dah ehs
.weiv fo dleif reh otni kcab deppets naicinhcet eht rof meht denrecnoc evah tsum ecnelis reH
.DUH lanretni reh otno dehsalf noitamrofni dna laudividni hcae deggat eniltuo eulb elap A
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,timda ot dah ehs lufpleh saw tahT
.tcapmoc dna krad ,esle gnihtemos yb decalper neeb dna enog dah rettam larberec deruoloc thgil eht
.htiw nigeb ot stun elttil a neeb dah ehs esuaceb saw ti detcepsus ehs yllanosreP
.neerg smetsys lla
YLSUOIVERP SKEEW EERHT
.llet dluoc ehs sa raf sa noitanigami ro ytilaudividni ,ytilanosrep fo ssol on htiw dnA
,enif m’I“ ”?KO uoy erA“
”?rae ruoy htiw gnorw s’tahW“
;yldrawni detcelfer ehs sa mlac saw ehs hturt nI
.ytsedom dedaelp dah ehs ,smsinahcem lanretni reh ta kool a evah ot detnaw dah dna reenigne na saw snisuoc reh fo enO
,egarots mret-gnol otni ti evohs ot deirt niaga dna yromem eht dellecnac ehS
.level namuh a no tcaretni dluoc ehs os sessecorp latnem reh nwod wols ot deriuqer neeb dah ehs yhw osla dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.efil wen reh otni ,elbat yrev siht no detavitcaer
.namuh a rof dednetni neeb reven dah ti tpecnoc-fo-foorp latnemirepxe na
”tuo uoy kaerf ot tnaw t’ndid eW“
sdrocer evitagitsevni eht ot ssecca deniag dna dnuof ylisae dah ehs tnaem seitilibapac detsoob IA wen reh
,enustiK citleC yb
tsehc reh deborp sregnif trepxE
.regnarts hcum saw
.neeb syawla dah ti hturt ni hguoht
.tsujda ot dna deneppah dah tahw htiw smret ot emoc ot ecaps dna emit erom reh evag ti ,dalg saw ehS
DUH lanretni reh ;nwod yaw denrut neeb dah snoitome reh taht erew deciton ehs sgniht tsrif eht fo enO
,enustiK citleC yb
eussi eht tuoba reh tnorfnoc ot dediced dah aluaP
ekil…elbat gnitarepo eht no nekow dah ehs nehT
.tnemegdelwonkca ni liat reh dekcilf yllausac ehs dna dessap ehs sa kcul doog reh dehsiw tsinoitpecer eht
.detpme-erp neeb dah ehs yltnerappa tub ecivres siht ta
.tobor fo tros emos saw ehs emussa ot demees elpoep tsom dna sraey tnecer ni ssergorp taerg edam dah ecnegilletnI-laicifitrA
.yltnatsni tsomla deid dah eugaelloc reh
seussi eseht tuoba cinilc eht detcatnoc ylsuoiverp tcaf ni dah ehS ”?yhw
”?rae ym htiw gnorw s’tahW ?yhW“
”?yltcaxe yhw ecalp gnikat saw siht em llet t’ndid uoy dnA“
,eciov lanigiro reh erutpacer ot elba neeb reven dah ehs troffe dna ecitcarp etipseD
,desaeler neeb dah ehs litnu derrucco neve dah ti taht erawanu neeb dah ehs dna
,raelc kcab emac ti ,tset-fles draob-no na nar ehs ylkciuQ
,noitasrevnoc eht pu dekcip ti sa drocca nwo sti fo devom dna detator rae-tfel reH
reh fo tnorf ni yalpsid a gnuws yehT
,sgrobyc-latot lanoitcnuf os ro nezod a ylno erew ereht dlrow eht lla nI
.fo elbapac won saw ehs tahw derednow ehS
.hguorht dael saw ehs dna nepo gnuws erew srood-elbuod eht sa noitanitsed rieht ta desuap yehT
.llew os detpada dah ehs yhw enimreted ot yduts dna noitanimaxe htped-ni dna evisnetxe ot tcejbus neeb dah ehS
.ti otni reh decalpme dah yeht dna elbaliava yletaidemmi ydob citenrebyc ylno eht neeb dah ti truh neeb dah ehs nehW
,lacinilc dna mlac ,denialpxe naicinhcet ehT
,ylpeed reh debrutsid dah ti taht denrael dah ehs nehW
.reh detaefed tsomla dah dna lufsserts ylralucitrap neeb dah sriats fo thgilf a nwod og ot gnitpmettA
.enustiK citleC yb
,flesreh derevocer dah ehs litnu tuo emoc ton did dna demlehwrevo moor reh ot detaerter dah ehS
,krowten ylimaf dednetxe evitroppus a hcus evah ot ykcul saw ehs taht desingocer ehS
,tfel ydob lanigiro reh fo gnihton saw erehT
.eviecer ot deunitnoc dna ,deviecer dah ehs eracretfa eht tuoba nialpmoc ton dluoc yllaer ehs
.llef dna esor pit-liat reH
.gnisselb dexim yltcnitsid a ,gninekawa reh fo tnemom eht morf llacer tcefrep dah ehs hguohT
.epoc ot elba neeb dah ehs yhw nosaer egral a saw ti
;noitcerid serugif detius eht fo rehtona ta edis reh no eil ot dedeecorp neht sehcnuah reh no tas ehS
.yrenihcam gnidnuorrus eht htiw egrem ot demees mrof reh sa ddo yltcnitsid tlef ehs dna
.tnereffid yna leef t’ndid yllaer ehs
.gnitirw reh rof noitaripsni sdnif netfo ehs erehw
,desilibats neht derekcilf metsys lausiv reH  ”.em tiH“
,enod dah ehs sa sisehtsorP-ydoB-lluF enogrednu dah ohw wef erew erehT
,tluciffid neeb dah shtnom wef tsrif ehT  …siht
.lrigloohcs tneidebosid a ekil leef reh edam dah tI
.tnedicni eht retfa nekow neeb tsrif dah ehs nehw ot ralimis ylgniyrrow saw siht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.tnaem mret taht tahw niatrec yleritne t’nsaw ti hguoht
,detavitca neeb tsrif dah ehs tnemom eht morf ecalp ekat ot nugeb dah ssecorp eht
,steerts ytic eht gnola deddap ehs sa secnalg suoiruc werd aluaP    enihcaM eht ni tsohG   :ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC
.deraeppa egami eht sa evitcepsrep sdrawedis reh morf dehctaw ehs dna
.deklaw yeht sa ylisae dettahc yeht dna yrevocer dna tnemtaert lanigiro reh ni devlovni neeb dah rebmem ffats ehT
.gniyonna saw hcihw
”enihcaM eht ni tsohG“ saw sihT
.tneserp tub eltbus ,eciov s’naicinhcet eht ni sserts eht tceted dluoc ehS
.sksat tselpmis eht neve nraeler ot deriuqer neeb dah ehs erehw noitatilibaher evisnetxe enogrednu dah ehs
.denilced neeb dah tseuqer eht tub enecs eht ta nekat neeb dah taht sotohp eht ees ot deksa dah ehS
”enihcaM eht ni tsohG“   yojne esaelP
,derevocer ylluf ehs litnu stnerap reh htiw evil ot enog dah ehS
daD regdaB yldduC
.ruomuh fo esnes a dedeen uoy ylniatreC
.htuom a evah ton did ydob siht taht tcaf eht dethgilhgih osla ti