.ereht gnidnats enialB was eh ,pu ekow ttehR nehW
.emoceb dah seert eht lla dlo woh deciton eh
.flesmih yojne ttehR tel tsuj eh
,deilper xof eht ,seye sih gnilloR ”?drowssaP“
,kliM yevraH etal eht ot llac a yltsom saw esarhp eht dootsrednu eh elihW
.yltfos wap s’ttehR gnizeeuqs ,dias enialB ”,yrros m’I“
.worb a dehcra ttehR
.maerd eht otni kcab og ot detnaw eH
.dnuorg nedal-eldeen enip eht no
.taorht sih pu elttar psag a tlef ttehR
9102 tsuguA – tneserP
.wodniw eht tuo gnikool dna liat sih gnikorts
### .eman tnereffid a yb og ot desu eh
ediseb tis ot emac neht dna nrecnoc htiw rehto hcae ta dekool sexof gnidnats owt ehT ”?esirprus siht ewo I od
.daor eht nwod deeps pu dekcip xof eht ,gniffuH
,sih ta dettaws wap A tneserP
.tfel sllip wef a etiuq llits erew erehT
,redrah gniyrc detrats eh dna
,mih rof dne eht saw ti thguoht eh
.eciov sih esiar ot deirt eh ,rood eht ta kconk a draeh ttehR nehW
.evah t’ndluohs eh llew ,wA“ .dehsulb enialB
.yaweerht cisab a pu tes ot shtnom sekat ti ,woN
hsiws tsethgils eht tsuj
,yromem otni kcab
.nuf eht ni nioj ot meht gnigru
”.thginot luferac eb“
,taorht sih fo kcab eht tih muc eht nehW
”?ecalp ruo ot gnimoc elbatrofmoc leef uoy dluow
.dniw eht ni delttar mih evoba sevael eht neve toN
.meht dellif kool suoveihcsim a tub
.sevlesmeht decneirepxe sah rohtua eht gnihtemos dna
,sgel sih ni selcsum eht gnisserac
,tuo tog sucraM nehW
.taorht ruoy truh ll’uoY .ebab ,klat ot yrt t’noD“
.dehsinimid dah elcric eht dna
drawrof denael xof desiar eht
”?haey ,gnikcuf er’uoy ohw luferac eb tsuj ,dnuora gniog recnac god yag eht htiw tuB
.gnos ecnad dlo na ekil dednuos taht gnihtemos ,gnihtemos draeh nalaG
s’ttehR .nomannic dna redneval
.sraet tI .uoy no sraew
.oot uoy ekil I ,raf os gniees m’I tahw morF
,sdem eht ot sknaht ,retteb tog sucraM yad ehT .deddon nalaG
,rood eht gnisolc ,detrats flow eht ”,yeH“ ”.ebab ,sknahT“
.rrum ho ,sraeb dna ,sregit ,snoil
.xob eht teg uoy ,sey yas uoy fI
.gnirevihs dna detaicame saw ydob elohw siH
,moortser kcab eht ot deklaw ttehR sA
.tsap eht fo snoitanracni lluf erew yeht
xob llams a dah enialB dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,seye s’ttehR ni pu gnillew detrats sraeT ”?su yrram uoy lliW“
,edaf ot nageb flow ehT
.liospot nezorf eht ot sllip eht gnikconk
.yawa raf leef uoy elihw neve ,diviv si
.teiuq os erew sdoow ehT
.dekcilf srae s’enialB
### .sexofeltneg owt sih htiw gniddew a ta
drawA yraretiL adbmaL a rof detanimon erew yehT
.sthgil gnirekcilf eht dima bolb a sa deraeppa yeht tey
,tarksuM bulC eht fo—
.niaga meht ees reven d’eh tnaem ti
.detnurg flow ehT
.oot ,pets hcae htiw decnuob ylleb sih dna
A“ .denediw seye s’enialB
.kniw a flow eht evag dna strohs sih fo dnabtsiaw eht ni sbmuht sih dekooh xof ehT
,tarksuM bulC eht fo retnec eht ni seidob fo ssam a saw tI
.ydob sih ni duorp tlef eh
.rood nori eht fo pot eht ta devom tols a dna
,mih devol llits sucraM dna enialB tuB
.noitanigami eht ot elttil yrev gnivael ,snaej rehtael thgit fo pil eht revo gnignah hcamots dnutor sih
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.gnihgual detrats htob yeht neht dna
.mih rof feiler a hcus saw
,xof rehto eht ,yllaniF
,gnihguaL ”.uoy tsuJ“
.dloc saw ria eht dna
.yawyna dewollaws eh neht tub
.selttob llip owt was dna edisni dekool eH
,kramer eht morf deid tuoba tsuj enialB
.ereht eno on saw erehT
:mih dnuora erew elpoep fo sdnik llA
.thguoht ttehR ,mraw os tlef tI
:taht eb tsuj syawla
.sserP lesaeW yb dehsilbup
.ssik a mih evag dna dneirfyob sih ot denrut ttehR
,enal yromem nwod dna
.s’enialB saw ti sa hcum sa emit tsrif sih yllacinhcet saw ti ,srentrap ylop rehto wenk eh elihW
”.gnihtemos ro tsap eht ni detcejer I yug emos eb thgim uoy thguohT .ekas s’kcuf rof ,uoy teem ot suovren tib a saw em fo traP
.senip eht gnoma liat der a fo
ekil saw ti tahw wonk t’nod
.craM detset yeht…ebab yeH“
### .os did eh elihw hcni na nwod strohs sih fo dnabtsiaw eht gnisaet
trihs sih fo ralloc eht yb drawrof enialB dellup
.esolc sucraM dezeeuqs dna dereens enialB
nekat dah eh liart a saw ti dna
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT dna sserP taotS retsiniS rof rotide na si ohw
.nomannic dna redneval ,ereht
”.oot ,ti tog s’eh…s’eH
.sdnoces wef a retfa dedisbus tub
.ni emac sexof eht fo eno nehw thgin ta net dnuora saw tI .tsrif ta ton
,retal rood eht no kconk A
.tfel sih no seert eht hguorht decnad thgilnus eht dna
.siht ekil nepo eht ni sdnah gnidloh skool dnoces teg neve t’ndluow yeht
,taots gnuoy a ,esrun ehT
.skcus dlo gnitteG
.enialB ot xob eht gnidnah ,dias sucraM
s’ttehR .yllanif uoy teem ot eciN !woW“
.tuons s’ttehR no ssik a detnalp dna pu emac xof rehto siht
.htuom sih otni evif deppop eH
.oot draeh I tahw s’taht ,haeY“ .deddon sucraM
,elbatrofmocnu leef dluoc enialB erofeb nehT
### .nwog etihw taht ni lufituaeb dekool eh ,htaed ni neve—
.haeY“ .deddon enialB
,eert a yb dedracsid gnieb pu dedne dah raewrednu dna strohs sih taht yldetaleb deciton eH
,enotsevarg eht tsap tsuj
,sreppop fo tih a gnikat ekil saw tI
.yawa gniklaw erofeb daeh eht no xof eht dettap dna tuo dellup flow eht ,nehT
,desserd teg mih depleh
,dias ttehR ”?rO“ ”.xob a ro
,xof-f tnallag-g—nallaG-G“ ”?ebaB“
”.si ti ohw wonk uoY .vraM ,no emoc ,hO“
.tarksuM bulC eht ta yalperof elttil yrev saw erehT
.ereh dekan yldemahsanu saw eh yaw eht neeb evah dluoc tI
.sexof ym fo eno tsol ydaerla I tuB“
,sselehtenon ereht saw ti tub
,aibohpores htiw slaed yrots sihT
”.neht elddim teg I sseuG .kcuF“
,deeps sih kcart ot stegdag tsewen eht lla dah eh dna ,yltnecer snohtaram gniod neeb dah eH .nur ot
drawrof denael nalaG
.nalaG dewollaws sdoow ehT tneserP
nehw fo ,nomannic dna ,redneval ,sexof fo
,elpoep yag neve ,yadot elpoep tsoM
”?thginot diar a eb ot desoppus ereht sI
,dias ttehR ”,enialB teeM
ésopxe VIH na nettirw osla evah yeht dna
,gnils eht ni detautis saw eh emit eht yB
,esruoc fo ,dna ,ebul eht ,rehtael eht ,muc eht ,taews eht :lla ti dellems eH
,deklaw eh sa ,dlo sraey ytriht tuoba tsap a
yltnecer yllaicepse ,netfo thguoht eH
sdoow eht otni deggoj dna nrut prahs a koot eH
,nekops erew sdrow oN
ylpeed gnilahni ,sllab s’xof gnidnats eht otni eson sih desserp dna
,yllaudarG .yracs
.rehtie sucraM pots t’ndluoc
,detsixe rehto eht wenk rehtien dna ,bulc a otni deklaw sexof owT
.ssilb ni dne lla dluow ti dna ,lla ti dne dluoc eH .ti od dluoc eH
.noisiv derrulb sih hguorht raeppa smrof was eh
,wol A ”—y evol-l I
,ydob sih gnirolpxe stsohg rehto eht gnirongI
”.oot uoy teem ot dalg m’I
,evom ot doog tlef tsuj ti tuB
,daor eht no daeha pU
.tuoba uoy gnillet neeb ev’I eituc eht si siht ,sucraM“
.dias eciov ffurg eht ”?drowssaP“
.pord tsal yreve rof flow eht gniklim
,ecaps eht tuohguorht
.laer eb ot siht rof ,gnihtyna naht erom ,detnaw eH
.daeh sih koohs ttehR
tahw oT“ .hguoc a htiw dias ttehR ”,owt uoy ,thgirla ,thgirlA“ ”.revol gnirutrun a eb d’ehs wonk uoY
,slanimirC doolB dellac
.semit sseltnuoc ttehR ot ti enod dah sucraM
”!yeH“ ”!mottob llac I“
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,mih dnuora dna mih evoba derewot seert ehT
”?gnorw od ew did tahW
”?ti si tahW ?taht gniod peek uoy od yhw ,ebaB“
,VIH htiw gnivil elpoep drawot noitanimircsid dna noitazitamgits eht si hcihw
.syad retteb sih fo eno ton saw sihT
”.craM ,meht ees dluoc I
.nwod tuhs saw ti erofeb rodnelps ygnurg sti lla ni
”.yhsulb lla gnitteg er’uoY
.ti tsniaga kcab sih detser dna eert a ta deppots eh ,eros swap siH
,bulc eht ,seiromem eht
”.ylimaf gnieb tuohtiw ereh ni tog htob uoy tuo sdnif esrun eht erofeb pu yrruH“
dnah ’sucraM gnidloh
,sllab sih no ylthgil gnillup dna gnildnof
### .yug siht tuoba emoh kcab dneirfyob sih llet ot tiaw t’ndluoc eH
.oot ,mih dessik dna
ylkaew dehgual ttehR ”!esirpruS“
.tsol efil a rof doots
.srehto naht retteb erew syad emos dnA .erot tI
kcab eht ot yaw sih edam eh sA
.laer eb ton dluoc siht ,oN .seenk dna sdnah sih ot despalloc eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ssa sih gnideerb noillats eht ot suoivilbo ,ssik taht otni tlem
,dekool eh nehw ,emit sihT .pans giwt rehtona draeh eh ,nehT
.oot deniarts dekool eh
.yad a llip a koot eh sa gnol sa esle enoyna yllaretil
detfaw ksum larutan sih dna
.sessam eht erofeb dekan saw eh woN
,drah saw kcoc s’ttehR ecnO
?enialB ,rettam eht s’tahw ,hO“ .dehgual sucraM
”.rehtie uoy esol ot tnaw t’nod I .yrros m’I“
.deid dah xof rieht ecnis yad eht ot sraey ytnewt deedni saw tI
denrut nalaG ,yllautnevE
.efil sih ni sdot eht fo rehtie ton yllaicepse ,enoyna nopu ti hsiw t’ndluow dna lleh ekil tlef eH
.ni emoc ot meht rof derutseg dna
.niaga airohpue taht ni tsol saw eh ekil tlef eH
,oS“ .yawa dekool dna yltnesba rae eno fo kcab eht dehctarcs eH
,kcoc s’flow eht ta deppal eh ,ylregaE
,dnoces a rof deppord waj s’enialB
,deirram llits yeht
flesmih tlef eh dna
,esnetni tlef ti ;laer leef tsuj t’ndid ti fo llA
.delims ttehR ”.sey kcuF“
.dnim ni bulc eht fo erutan eht htiw ,erdnetne elbuod eht fo erawa naht erom saw eh
;dedraug ti seiromem eht revo lenitnes tnelis a ekil dekool eert ralugnis hcaE
.noitarepsed ro ,ytip ro ,worros fo ton erew yehT .degnahc
”.noitidnoc eno tsuj s’ereht tuB
spih s’flow eht dnuora smra sih depparw dna ni deklaw eH
5891 rebotcO :tsaP
,secivres noitnevretni ylrae rof
:sllems eht erew tsom eht ttehR tih tahw ,thgis eht naht erom neve tuB
.semit tsap tuoba gnicsinimer saw eh
.wap eerf sih htiw seye sih depiw dna nwod tas enialB ”…I .gnihtyreve
emoceb dah ecalp ehT .ereh thgir
.enialB ta neht rood eht ta dekool eh sa ecno dekcilf srae siH
.kcoc s’xof ylkcis eht dekorts sucraM elihw
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,gnivlossid smrof eht erew
.waptoof sih htiw renob s’enialB gnikorts tpek tsuj ttehR dna
.denmad eb niar ,ti teg ot dennalp eh dna
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
dna…esnetni erom hcum tsuj
,’elbatcetednu‘ dna yhtlaeh era yeht
,sexof sih fo htob devol eh tuB
,lwoH notsruhT yb
.tsil taht no ereht thgir si wonk uoy enoyreve
.recnac god yag eht dellac neeb emit a nopu ecno dah hcihw ,esaesid god rekcart sih rof saw enO
.emit tsrif eht rof DH ni lla meht gniees saw eh ekil ,liated lluf ni lla meht was nalaG
9891 yaM–tsaP
,rethgual eht dimA
,”rednevaL dna nomanniC fo stsohG“
”.oot ,stsohg yldneirf era erehT
,dnuos eht fo ecruos eht ees ot dnuora daeh sih deppihw eH
”?yllaer ,ekiL ?siht tuoba erus htob uoy era…hu
.ereht secaf dezilanretni dna was ylerar elpoeP
,tsap eht fo stsohg eht gnisahc
.modeerf dna ytivitisop xes fo noitarbelec fo dnik a erew secaps esoht ,s08 eht ni kcab ,neht kcaB
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.rehtie erofeb uoy gniteem dellacer t’ndah I
,5102 ni VIH htiw desongaiD
.tnemesuma s’ttehR dna sucraM ot hcum
### —htiw derevihs nalaG
,sgel s’enialB neewteb ti desserp dna
toof sih detfil eH
,nosinu ni gniyas erofeb
.enola ton er’uoy rebmemer dna
,nalaG ot ,eert hcae
,erom daeh sih koohs tsuj ttehR tuB
,mih dessik xof redlo eht sa
.xob eht denepo sucraM
.pu depmuj enialB dna ,ot pu dekooh saw ttehR enihcam eht morf dednuos peeb gniniltalf
”.seituc ,kcab thgir eb ll’I
.dehsilpmocca gnileef
,lwoH notsruhT yb ,GNAF fo emulov s’raey tsal ni dehsilbup yllanigiro
,siht ekil noitnetta fo retnec eht gnieb ot desu t’nsaw eH
.ruf ylleb etihw s’xof eht hguorht wap a gnibbur
.kcid sih ot nwod detniop
.puorg eht ni oga sraey evif-ytriht tarksuM bulC eht morf draug thgin flow eht dezingocer eh thguoht eH .delims eH
.lehctas sih ot kcab yaw sih gnikam
ni erehwemos
,deilper ttehR ”,lla ta toN“
”rednevaL dna nomanniC fo stsohG“ saw sihT
,ti tuoba thguoht eh erom ehT
”.gniddew eht gninnalp trats ll’ew ,ereh fo tuo kcuf eht teg uoy ecnO .dooG“
,llorts a ot dewols goj sih sA
N“ .siht fo lla hguorht gniog ttehR tpek tahw fo flah eno saw enialB
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.hguone gnorts t’nsaw I yrros m’I“
,detrats ohw eno eht saw enialB
.sih fo ksum larutan taht neeb evah dluoc tI
swap s’rehto hcae dezeeuqs sexof owt ehT
.daeh sih ekahs ot deirt eH
”!ragluv os syawlA“
.srenroc krad ni smoor etavirp yltsom desirpmoc flesti bulc ehT ”.ti tog uoY“
.sbro eht ta gnikcil dna
daeh sih revo trihs sih dellup eh
,thgir draeh dah eh erus ekam ot gnikcehc
.yponac eht ta pu derats dna
.s’enialB dloh ot ssorca wap a dehcaer sucraM ”?erus uoy erA-
,gnikahs saw wap siH
.mug nomannic sih gniwehc syawla saw xof tahT
.enola reverof neeb evah dluow eh deirrow dah eH
.tnereffid eb thgim yadot…yadot tuB
.evol ni yldam ydaerla saw ttehR dnA
,craM sih enigami t’ndluoc eH
,dna ,eeffoc revo erom emos tahc nac eW
.niaga reve ton ebyaM
.oga sraey evif-ytriht erew yeht ekil t’nerew sgnihT
,srebmun eht gnitirw dehsinif xof eht nehw nevE
.yawa dekcol neeb dah taht gnihtemos
:ylneddus stnecs wen erew erehT
sa efil a yhtlaeh sa dna gnol sa evil dluoc eh os ti edam dah enicidem fo secnavda ehT
.yteixna htiw gnihctiwt eson sih
.ttehR rof detcere dah yeht enotsevarg eht was dna
.depmuj eh sa dne no doots ruf s’enialB
.lortnoc tuohtiw tpew dna
”rednevaL dna nomanniC fo stsohG“:yojne esaelP
”.thgirlA“ .dehsulb enialB ”?eM“
”.og uoy tel t’now I“ .dias eh ”,oN“
,drawrof dereggats eH
.meht ees dluoc I
;thgiew esol ot goj t’ndid eH
.yalp emoc ot lla dna yna gnitivni ,mih dniheb ylwols liat sih dehsiws eh yaw eht neeb tsuj evah dluoc ti rO
,llih eht fo pot eht dehcaer yeht nehW
,hcamots s’ttehR no stigid kcalb ,egral ni rebmun enohp sih nwod etorw xof redlo eht elihW
.hgual a htiw mra sih dehcnup ttehR
seye s’ttehR ni sraet ehT
,dne eht rof esuoh sih no pu emoc ot tuoba saw eh
,nalaG s’xof sih syawla
.gnihton tlef eh ,tsrif tA
eert eht tsniaga kcab daeh sih denael eH
.seert eht gnoma dekan
,ti htiw ko llits er’uoy fi
.taorht s’nalaG tsniaga gnisserp pit eht
,sisongaid sih tuoba nepo gnieb rof flesmih llik ot nalaG dlot elpoep nehW .t’nsaw ti tub
.daor eht ees regnol on dluoc eh ,sllih wef a dna setunim wef a retfA
tneloiv emaceb shguoc ehT
,gnileef larecsiv a hcus saw
,ereh bulc xes a doots ecno dah erehT
,dias dah srotcod eht tahw meht llet ot traeh eht evah t’ndid ttehR
;stsohg elbisivni on erew esehT
,stsohg yrgnuh fo kcap a fo tsdim eht ni ,saw eh ereh tub
.eveileb ot tahw wonk ton did nalaG tneserP
.yllanif deganam eh ”…on-
.nomannic eht etsat dluoc eH
margorp weiveR kooB yrruF eht nur osla yehT
.elzzumyarg a dellac gnieb won saw tahw saw eH
.dekrims xof rehto ehT
.cimedipe esaesid god rekcart eht saw ereht esruoc fo dnA
.kaeps ot ytiliba eht tsol ydaerla dah eh tub ,delims eH
.kcab htgnerts lluf sih tog sucraM nehw evarg s’ttehR yb ti did yeht dna
,daeh sih raen sniahc eht gnippirg swap sih dna sniahc eht gnola sparts no gnitser selkna sih
.sraey fo elpuoc a tsuj ni sdneirf ruoy fo tsom esol ot
.deprihc sdrib gninrom ylrae oN
.yaw on saw erehT
,srae sih fo kcilf a dna nirg a htiW
.detrats sucraM ”,oS“ .redluohs ’sucraM revo mra na gnipparw dna kcab gninael ,enialB fo dias ttehR ”,xof tnallag ym syawla ,heH“
hsiw sih nettog dah ttehR taht saw owt dna
,flow hsiraeb a laever ot
,ecaf knalb s’xof eht revo teehs etihw eht dellup rotcod a dna eh sa dehctaw enialB dna ,moor eht fo tuo mih decrof
.stnap sih fo hctorc eht tsniaga gnihsurb
,thgilnus naht tsim erom saw erehT
srewolf uoy thguorb eW“
,drow rieht ot eurT
dluow ti nalaG ot tub ,DDT ot tsol erew ohw
.daeh sih koohs dna denettalf srae s’enialB
.enola saw eh tub
,pit eht ssorca eugnot sih gnikcilf no gnisucof tsuj
sraey wef a fo esruoc eht revo wonk uoy enoyreve tsomla gnisol tub ,tniop siht yb oga sraey ytnewt revo saw tI
esoht gnitaromemmoc ,bulC eht fo renwo suoiverp eht ot sknaht ,tserof tnadrev a
.swap s’ttehR dna s’enialB htob dezeeuqs
.dias sucraM ”,reh kcuf ,hA“
mih dellac dah ttehR tahw taht saw eno
.sdrawA yraretiL oeL eht etatilicaf dna
,no neht morf eman sih eb dluow
,elohliat s’ttehR gnidnuop saw noillats a elihW
”?sronoh eht od ot ekil uoy dluoW“ .yadot ton
.ydaerla syug eseht fo driht a yb dekcuf neeb ylbaborp dah dna semit sseltnuoc ereh neeb dah eh hguoht neve
.htaed fo tnemunom a
.oot ,enips sih ssorca msaps worros tlef eH
.hself devarc yeht dna
.erom htaerb sih gnisol detrats dah eh
”.truh t’now…erom wef a tsuJ“
.egdelwonk ym ot toN“
ttehR“
fo stfaw delahni eh
.raey a semit elpuoc a og thgim I“
.emit tnereffid a saw tI
.esruoc fO .uoy yrram lliw I esruoc fO“ ,dias dna delims ttehR
kcab sih dettap wap ehT
,ydaerla sruoh elpuoc a neeb dah tI
,goj gninrom sih rof lausU
,muc ,sreppop ,skcoc fo rulb a emaceb thgin ehT .elttil yreV
.srae sih ni gnidnuop detrats traeh siH
”.srewolf eht teg uoy ,on yas uoy fI
.mih depolevne ssendloc ,nehT
.detnap eh sa ria eht ta deppal eugnot sih dna ,mih fo tnorf ni dezillatsyrc
,sknird retfa“ ,detrats ttehR ”,yaS“
.renroc eht ni elip a otni strohs sih dna ti werht dna
regnif a deggaw flow eht erofeb
.taht meht wohs ot detnaw eh dna
.nwod peed ssenilenol taht tlef llits eh ,syad tsoM
.ti dnuora depparw nobbir der htiw
.gnivom llits saw taht llikdaor ekil dekool eH
.llits gnibbos ,tsehc s’xof eht otni ecaf sih desserp dna
?sucraM saw erehW .denworf eh ,nehT
.tuo kcab ot eb dluow eh ylekil erom eht
.secalp dehctiws sucraM dna enialB ,nehT
.gnidnats llits seno tsal eht fo eno er’uoy ekil leef uoy litnu gniraet speek tI
.eno citnamor a ton ,tuls lauxes a yllausu saw eH
.dias nalaG ”,oga sraey deid uoy thguoht I ?ereh er’uoY
,deirc dah eh erehw seert eht tsap tsuJ
.tnemssarrabme ni tuons sih revo wap a depmalc neht dna
”?noitseuq eht s’tahw…sseug I“
.hguorht sllab sih dezeeuqs dna
.wodniw eht tuo dekool dna eciov wol a ni denihw tsuj enialB
.taht rof ydaer t’nsaw eh tub
lwoH notsruhT yb
,tsehc sih no ruf eht hguorht gnikrow
,naicitilop yag ylnepo na
.erus rof ,gninialpmoc em hctac t’noW
.siht fo lla rof ezigolopa enialB tel ot desufer eH
9891 tsuguA –tsaP ###
.tnew eh raf woh erac t’ndid eH
.ydob s’xof eht gnirimda tsuj
,retal sraey desongaid saw nalaG nehW
.tarksuM bulC eht
.xes detcetorpnu hguorht neve VIH timsnart ot elbanu er’yeht snaem hcihw
”—g-g-g yM .gnorts-s ytnelp er’uoy-y-
.teiuq ooT .tnelis saw tI
.ti denepo dna elttob llip eht tuo dellup eH
,llah eht nwod sthgil gnihsalf eht drawot gniklaw llitS
.ydaerla kcuf sa esolc era ttehR dna uoy wonk I ,kooL“
.revo uoy evah ot evol dluow ew
lla erew dnuora elbmesne eht ezilaer ot ylno
.gnihguoc erofeb thguoht ni fi sa yawa dekool ttehR ”…kO“
.oot gniraeh sih tceffa ot gnitrats t’nsaw esaesid god rekcart eht taht dna
,elohliat sih dekrow dna liat s’ttehR rednu bmuht a desserp enialB
,VIH htiw desongaid yltnecer si wonk uoy enoemos ro uoy fI
,gninrom siht ecnis derewohs t’ndah eh ,liat sih rednu tuo denaelc dah eh elihW
”.uoy rof noitisoporp…a evah ew ,lleW“
tlef eh worros reehs eht htiw detrotnoc ecaf siH
.llamrepus ro tol gnikrap a eb tsuj d’ti ,esiwrehtO
,dias enialB dna sucraM ,nosinu nI
,thginot bulc eht morf gnitnaw saw eh tahw wenk eH
,pu dekool eh nehw tuB
.noitcerid sih gninrut syug deciton eh ,gnils tnacav a saw ereht erehw
,flesmih gniyojne saw eh ekil dekool xof eht elihW
,recnac god yag siht gnidrager yaw rieht tog sdef eht ecniS
”.riaf ton s’tI .craM ,riaf ton s’tI“
.seye dekaos-raet s’enialB otni pu gnikool
,gniwollaws erofeb desuap eH
eb ot desu lla tI
.hcamots s’ttehR drawot derutseg eH ”?dnim uoy dluoW“
.regnif a rof gib oot ylraelc saw tI .gnir denots-der A
,dias ttehR ”,regnarts ,yeH“
.seert eht otni kcab
,teehs eht rednu wap a gnihcaeR
.evah dluohs I sa luferac sa…gnieb t’nsaw I
thguac eh lla dna ,dnuora kcab denrut nalaG
,gnitirW esoR kcalB yb dehsilbup
,redisnocer ot fi sa
.sdoow eht fo tuo mih ediug ot detrats dna
,reniD dooweceelF eht ,eno siht ekil ecaps yag a ni dnA
.yrros os m’I…yrros m’I“
.raey fo emit siht dnuora yllaicepse ,semit ynam
,kcab sseltrihs sih tsniaga decnuob kcapkcab siH
I won dna ,kcis gnitteg morf uoy pots t’ndluoc I
5891 rebmeceD – tsaP
,ti was eh thguoht eh
.rekram a tuo dellup xof eht
,secaf on ezingocer dluoc ttehR
,sllip eht koot I nehW
”.oot ,mih ssim I .evol ,ko s’tI“ ,dias ,sucraM
.moorhtab eht esu og annog m’I“
Y“ .keehc s’enialB desserac dna pu wap gnikahs sih dehcaer xof kcis ehT
.nalaG dnuora derettahs ecapsdaeh ehT
”.uoy fo htob esol ot tnaw t’nod I
”…yeh tuB .evol ,wonk I“
rediw denepo seye
.deipucco ydaerla sgnils dna—
,dedaf yltsom saw taht liart dlo na nekat dah eH
.deb latipsoh s’ttehR
.sdoow eht otni repeed dekool eH
ssa sih no gnitser saw eh litnu dlof seenk sih tel dna dehgis eH
,tis ot god a gnidnammoc nehw seod eno ekil sregnif sih gnippans ,dna reens a htiw yltnatcepxe mih ta nwod dekool draug flow ehT
.gnir kcoc a saw ti ezilaer ot hguoc eno fo noitarud eht ylno ttehR koot tI
seert eht neewteb tuo dekool sucraM
.rood eht denepo sexof sih fo htoB ”!ni emoC“
.rehtegot rulb ot detrats noisiv sih fo sroloc eht
.hguorht gniog saw eh gniht emas eht hguorht gniog ,craM sih
.aedi live na ,yas ot si hcihw ,aedi yxof a dah ttehR ,nehT
.gniod saw eh tahw wenk sucraM taht wenk ttehR
.ecarbme taht detivni dna dnuorg dloc eht no sgel sih daerps eh ,liat sih tsniaga desserp kcoc debrab s’enilef a sA
.ecnetnes htaed a t’nsaw tsuj tI
”.uoy tuoba tol a deklat
”?esoht era srewolf fo dnik tahw…mu…lleW“
tuoba…siht tuoba yrros os m’I
.pot porc a dna strohs trohs ni desserd saw eh ,steerts selegnA soL eht revo delttes dah taht dloc eht dna
.noitarimda fo erew yehT
.ecaf sih nwod demaerts sraet dna ,seiromem fo evaw eht ta
.oot ,ytiralc dlob ni ,scip kcid ro scip ecaf rehtie s’ereht dna ,e-ttonK nepo uoy ,syadawoN
piy a tuo tel xof ehT
.keew yreve kcehc dluow eh srepap eht ni seigolue eht
,stsohg rehto eht fo emos ta
.aera ysdoow elttil ro krap a aera eht gnikam fo gnikniht era yeht ,hguoht aera laitnediser nmad a fo egde eht no s’ti ecniS
.sregnif sih dexelf dna
”…kcab lla ti tnaw I…kcab lla ti tnaw I“ ,niaga revo dna revo gnirettum
.pu ttehR dekrow ylwols eh
rebmem s’xof eht revo gnir kcoc eht dekrow enialB
.nekat spets dna ,etar traeh
kcab sdneirf sih fo lla rof gnignol sih dna
,rehtruf ni kcoc sih dehsup dna srae eht yb mih debbarg flow ehT
.pans giwt a draeh eh litnU
,seman fo stsil eht dellacer eh ,seert eht otni dedaf serugif lufroloc eht sA
xof emosdnah eht ta pu delims tsuj eH
,yad a llip elgnis a gnikat dna
:tnemom taht ta sgniht owt wenk enialB
neM thgiartS rellirht yag rieht rof drawA wobniaR eht revO AALA dna
krowten erac SDIA/VIH lacol ruoy tcatnoc ot erus ekam
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.tlef ti suoirolg woh dna ereht teem d’eh nem eht lla derebmemer eH
,selppin sih revo swalc demmirt rieht gnidils
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
niar eht etipseD
.sllems rehto eht ot gnidda
.keehc s’flow eht no ssik a dekcep dna
.ti denepo dna kcapkcab sih ffo dellup eh ,nehT
”?ereht raluger a uoY ?tarksuM bulC eht ta gnikcuf tem syug uoy dias
sucraM ”.sey gnikcuf dna ,sey ,seY
,secaf eseht nees dah eh ecnis yrutnec a flah revo neeb dah tI
.mih dnuora elcric a mrof ot detrats dah syug
htaerb fo ffup hcaE
,wap sih ni srewolf fo teuquob a dah sucraM
saw…od ot dah eh llA .kcab lla ti evah dluoc eH .tsap eht ,revol sih
,ta kool ot syob eht rof wols dna ecin liat sih hsiws ot erus edam eh
.swap erab sih htaeneb dehcnurc sevael dna lios eht dna
.enog saw eh tub ,yromem eht retfa ,flow eht retfa esahc ot gniyrt ,drawrof delwarc eh
yadot yad laiceps taht htiw—
”.elihw a rof nwod tuhs annog era sbulc eht lla
.yawyna nwod ti gniraet er’yeht ,sediseb tuB
.wap sih barg ot tuo dehcaer dna was enialB
.sexof ,esruoc fo ,dna ,sevlow ,sesroH
.uoy rof noitseuq a evah eW
gnihtyrevE .eeffoc fo spuc eerht knard tsuj uoy tub devirped-peels er’uoy nehw ekil
.drawrof denael sucraM ”?tahW“
?mH“ ,dias dna redluohs sih revo dekool xof eht
.delttar kcas ehT
,sknird rieht htiw emac retiaw eht nehW
.wap a gnivaw ,dias enialB ”,haN“
”.pot llac ll’I sseug I ,thgirlA“ .dehgual enialB
,derettum nalaG ”…on ,on ,oN“
.draug eht detulas dna dehgual xof ehT
,daor eht revo dehsaw tsim gninrom ehT
.tols eht morf tuo deralg flow ylrub A
.mih no nwod erow ti fo lla ,emas eht lla tuB .t’ndid eh
.gniggaw llits liat sih tub talf srae ,dias sucraM ”,haeY“
,elbat eht ssorca denael ttehR
?nam ,kcuf eht tahW“
.ecarbme eht tsuj
nepo dekaerc rood ehT
sraey eht revo tub ,taerg tlef sgel siH
.evid eht ekat
.erac t’ndid eh tub ,erp fo lirdnet gnol a gnikael saw kcoc sih dna
,dehsulb dna kcab denael enialB
,sehtolc s’nalaG debbarg sucraM
.ecarbme esolc a ni mih dloh dna mih ediseb nwod leenk erugif eht tlef eH .mih debbur dna
.straeh rieht lla htiw
:koobecaF no tsil sdneirF a ot ralimis emaceb stsil eht woh dellacer eH
”.gnorts senob ruoy sekam kliM“
,eman s’dneirf taht was eh nehw tuB
.sllip gnikat tpek eH
.deraeppa xof dnoces eht nehw ytilaer ot deneprahs ylno dlrow ehT  .stsif neve dna
.ylkaew dehgual eH
goj a dehsinif syawla eH
.raluger tneuqerf repus a t’nerew uoy looc s’ti tuB
.gnissap s’ttehR hguorht teg rehto hcae depleh yeht
,ylregae dewollaws nalaG
.daetsni rehto eht debbarg dna elttob llip taht tsap devom wap sih tuB
,dehgual sucraM dna ttehR
.elbat eht ssorca xof eht ot gnirutseg elihw
”?worromot rO ?siht retfa snalp yna toG .eituc ,ereht yeH“
nwog etihw a ni ekil kool dluow eh tahw tuoba gnikniht ,emac ttehR
.rof desu eb lliw dnal eht tahw ni yas a steg renwo eht taerg s’tI
.eye ot eye erew yeht os ,pu tuons s’xof redlo eht dellup eH
.mih gnidiug tpek sucraM sa neve ,redluohs sih revo kool ot denrut eH
.lleh sa ecin saw ehS .dluow I ,haey kcuF“ ”.oot ,dluow uoY“
.flow gnixamilc eht no dekcus eh elihw htuom sih otni rednaw sregnif rieht gnittel
.dne ot ti tnaw t’ndid eh ,noitanicullah decudni-gurd a saw gniees saw eh tahw fI
.mih htiw yats ot stsohg eht detnaw eH
.ecaf sih ni kcoc der a saw ereht
,ydob sih derolpxe swap riehT
.won tnereffid demees sdoow eht ,wohemos tuB
.skeehc sih nwod gninnur sraet tlef nalaG dna
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.eb ot desu eh sa yrps sa ton saw nalaG
.redluohs ’sucraM delzzun eH
:kcab lla ti evah dluoc eH
”.esuoh eht ot kcab uoy klaw pleh ll’I ,nom’C“
annodraeB—cisum duol htiw sthgil eborts gnihsalf dah saera lartnec wef A
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.muc ,esruoc fo ,dna ,rehtael ,taews
,sexof owt eht neewteb dekool enialB
,nirg a htiw daeh sih gnikahs ,dias ttehR ”,gnidnob era owt uoy elihW“