.ssalc ni daer uoy yasse taht tuoba klat em draeh eh ecno
.snooccar yoB .snooccar ekil I
mih dlot einrE tahw morf wenk eH
,pu ekow I nehw oS
,htoob eht fo teef wef a nihtiw emac nooccar eht sA
.hctaw eht ni si ,terref a ,sdneirf ym fo enO"
.tcaf a s'taht dna ,uoy evah dluow esle eno oN"
:owt fo tsrif eht ni si yrots s’yadot dna
,revewoh ,egdirb eht dehcaer eh nehW
,yrots ym rof llaf etiuq t'ndid eH
,ti otni em dezitonpyh enoemos ro ,gniklawpeels elihw redrum a dettimmoc I rehtehw wonk t'nod llits I"
",rood eht morf renroc tsehtraf eht ni kooL
.ti dnif t'ndluoc dna ,ssarg eht ni sroodtuo ti rof gnikool saw I taht demaerd I
erehT" .eerht mih evag sicnarF
.neht eciov sih dnuof sicnarF ".saw
ti tub ,ksid elttil eht gnipeek neeb dah eh erehw tekcop eht otni dehcaer sicnarF
"?eb ot gniog ksat eht saw tahW"
"?ti maerd I did woh oS"
.yaw taht kcab og ot aedi dab a eb dluow ti taht yletaidemmi tsomla dediced tub
,thguohtretfa na sa tsomla ,dedda eh ",dnA"
,stseretni nwo ym tuoba wenk eh neht yB"
...dna ,ecalp niatrec a ni em dnif emoc ot uoy llet ot desoppus saw eH" "?tahW"
.uoy ekil od yllaer I tuB .won sraey rof ,sgniht eseht tlef I taht timda ot ton gniyrt ,flesym gnithgif neeb ev'I
em dellac dna em degguh ev'uoy emit yrevE
mih ot dellac dna devaw rab eht dniheb
.nekot eht nees evah emos dna
"?gninrom siht gnillik taht tuoba draeh ev'uoY"
,yaw emos ni si nekot eht tahw tuo dnif ot yrt ro esitrevda dluohs hctaw eht fI
.uoy ssik ot desufer evah t'ndluow I
,yrots elohw eht dlot sicnarF oS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.deksa sicnarF "?gnorw s'tahW"
",egnarts ylniatrec s'tI"
.raekcalB niW ro nosyerG yaJ dnif dluoc eh fi derednow eH
,”srettilG tahT llA“
.erus rof s'taht ,em t'nsaw tI"
.wonk uoy ,mih no uoy hsiw t'ndluow I"
.gnirebmemer ,desuap eh "...nehT
,tibah fo ecrof yb yrarbil eht drawot tuo detrats sicnarF
",oot gnihtemos uoy llet ot evah I"
smaerd naht rehto ,ecnedive on dah eH
.mih dezingocer dna pu dekool yaJ
,sih etisoppo taes a ot sicnarF devaw yaJ
.tekcop ym ni saw ti dna dekool I
.mih dlot sicnarF ",won gnivael ton m'I"
,sdneirf wen ekam ot redrah deirt dah sicnarF fI
,ylgnilliw ro ylgniwonk gniht ta hcus od reven dluow I ,naem I
?pu gnikaw tuohtiw ,gniklawpeels elihw ti enod evah I dluoc tub
.nooccar rehto eht desserdda ehs sa neve sicnarF ta gnikniw
,flU morf snoitcurtsni eht ,maerd eht tuoba
sa onimA yrruF dna ,lysaeW
.saw yllaer puorg eht tahw gniwonk tuohtiw ,slairetam yrotsih egelloc dlo emos morf ohR atE ahplA fo aedi eht deworrob I
,won yb pu denaelc neeb dah enecs elohw eht fi nevE
?neht niW tuoba tahw tuB
,daetsni mih ot emoc syawla dah yehT
.kcab sih nwod delevart dna
.sgniht suoregnad dna egnarts gniod dna
eman eht htiw gnihtemos gniod saw I wonk elpoep fo rebmun A
,wenk eh ,retnec htlaeh eht ta srolesnuoc erew erehT
.ylteiuq dias eh ",taht od t'noD"
.llew nottahC wonk t'ndid sicnarF
",gnorw enog sah gnihtyrevE"
rednu nozamA no dna ",ovitlA"
".em htiw eb ot uoy ekil d'I ,no emoC"
?esroh lesuorac dedaeh-nedoow a tsuj taht saw rO .esroh ecnassianeR a s'eh skniht ohw ,orevO ovitlA yb
.detcepxe yllamron evah dluow sicnarF taht ygrene eht htiw ton tub ,delims flow ehT
.erows eh won tub
.delggig lrig ehT
.dias eh ",pihsnoitaler a ni ro evol ni neeb reven ev'I"
,eert wolloh eht ni nopaew neddih eht
.deddon sicnarF .dias eh
,ohR atE ahplA lanigiro eht fo rednuof eht saw eh ,dnA
,hteet etihw prahs ynam dna swaj nepo htiw
.retteb od nac eH
.seilppus gnimoorg dna hsurbhtoot sih htiw reward eht otni ti kcuts dna tuo ti dellup ylitsah dna
htapwot dlo eht gnola klaw thgim eh taht thguoht emos htiw
.ria no gniklaw saw I ekil
.ma yllaer I" .dias flow eht ",yrros m'I" .og tel dna wap sih dezeeuqs yaJ
demialcorp letnil eht no tniap gnileep ehT
.edirp dna lortnoc fles sih niager dna
"?gninrom siht sa yltnecer sa
.ammelid sih tuoba kniht ot ton deirt sicnarF
.orevO ovitlA yb osla
,uoy htiw em pleh ot deerga eh dnA
,dias sicnarF ",yaJ ,wonk uoY"
.eman s'niW ta dekcirp srae sih
.mih htiw tuo og ot sessalc sih ni slrig fo eno teg ot detnaw eh esuaceb mih no ti deirt yllanigiro I
".ereht dnuorg eht no snekot ruo fo eno dnuof yeht ecnis yllaicepsE .si ti ,seY"
"?taht naem uoY ?yllaeR"
,sregnarts ot elbatipsoh yrev ton erew ytic eht fo saera emos taht
".lufwa s'tI" .dias eh ",pu denaelc neve yeht erofeb enecs eht tsap saw I" .deddon sicnarF
.daeH s'floW ehT dellac nrevat a ot ecnartne eht dessap eh ,renroc tsrif eht tA
ni nrut ot tuoba saw eH
.yaJ saw ti erus eb ot mih rof hguone doog t'nsaw thgil eht hguoht ,ereht htoob eht ni gnittis flow yarg a saw ereht ,hguone eruS
,mih ot gnirrefer tcaf ni saw ehs taht dezilaer sicnarF sa neve dna
dluow ti ,t'ndid uoy fi dna ,em rof tuo krow thgim uoy thguoht eH
.ecaf sih no niap taerg fo noisserpxe na htiw taes sih ni kcab denael flow ehT .dias sicnarF
.nwo sih htiw wap s'yaJ fo kcab eht dettap dna
htiw edosipe txen eht ni yrots siht eunitnoc eW
.won em etah ylbaborp ll'uoY .uoy ekiL
,”gninaW nooM suobbiG“ saw sihT
.sicnarF dlot eh ",daeha og ,eruS"
,tekcop tekcaj sih otni wap a gnittuP ".YC053
.gnihtyreve fo etips ni ,taht ta elkcuhc ot dah sicnarF ".em ssik ...dna
,won uoy ot on yas t'nac I"
ohR atE ahplA pu edam uoy oS"
?erofeb yad eht taht saw rO
,mih nekat dah einrE pohs esohw ot tnahcrem eniw eht morf noitcerid etisoppo eht ni teerts eht pu gnitratS
detacilpmoc a sa tsuj
,ydnarb eht gnisahcrup morf egnahc eht dah llits eh dnuof sicnarF
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
?morf emoc nekot eht did erehW
,mih raeh ylerab dluoc sicnarF taht yltfos os ,dias eh ",esuaceB"
,hguoht ,yrarbil eht ot kcab og ot gnilliwnu dna ssalc ni tis ot doom on ni gnieB
kniw s'lrig eht denruter sicnarF
.seye rebma demmir-tew htiw sicnarF ta kool ot elzzum sih desiar yaJ
".su dnif dluoc yeht
nekot ym dnif t'nac I ,lla fo tsriF
.raekcalB niW saw elpuoc eht fo flah rehto eht ,hguone eruS
...ot uoy llet mih evah ot gniog saw I"
.YC053 .tse eddeH sefloW"
"?mih dnif nac I erehw wonk uoy oD
.decnuonna eh ",sicnarF yddub ym s'tahT"
.rekniht ydaets dna peed a yltcaxe ton tub ,yug taerg a saw eimoor siH
noitingocer ni deknilb niW
.ksa ot dah tsuj sicnarF
.mih detnuah ytilibissop eht ,syad wef tsap eht fo secneirepxe sih htiw tey dna
.ereh thgir si eniM
.rebmem roines a eb ot dneterp dna uoy ot emoc dneirf a evah ot gniog saw I
,ytiniffA ruF no mih dnif nac uoY
",epoh em evig uoY"
,thguoht sicnarF ,lleW
.daeh sih koohs sicnarF "?sessalc oN
.rood eht evoba gnuh
.wonk ydaerla uoy sa ,dnik nwo ym naht evitcartta erom raf sevlow dnif I dnA
.erolpxe ot yad doog a eb thgim siht taht mih ot demees ti
.dettimmoc dah eh wonk t'ndid eh emirc a ssefnoc dna hctaw eht ot og tsuj ot ydaer t'nsaw eh dna
.deye-ediw ,dias sicnarF
",dal emosdnah siht rof uoy edart dluohs I ebyam ,niW ,hO"
,gnihtemos yrt retteb dah eh
,pu dehsinif eh ",ees uoy ,oS"
.flow eht ta deknilb sicnarF ".yawyna
.thguoht eh ,tsael ta taht tuoba hturt eht gnillet saw yaJ oS
.tluaf ym lla si siht esuaceb
.erehw wonk I kniht I dna" ,dias sicnarF
"?swap nwo ym htiw siht od em ekam ot dnim ym ni noitseggus a detnalp wohemos evah enoemos dluoc rO
.detacidni dah niW renroc ywodahs eht otni dereep dna ssalg sih koot sicnarF
.gniklawpeels tnerappa sih dna
,sicnarF ,ti nmaD" .seye sih debbur dna desuap flow eht "...I
,dias ehs ",pmul taerg uoy ,no emoC"
.deddon nooccar ehT
,shtao ot nevig ton saw sicnarF ".yltcefrep
.raelc yks eht dna tuo saw nus eht taht won
.ti ta kool ot tnaw t'ndid eh
.llaH supuL drawot kcab dna
"?od ot gniog ew era tahw woN
.em ot ti denoitnem eh tub enoyna llet ot desoppus t'nsaw eH
,dnuof dah eh ,semitemoS
.deerga sicnarF ",seY"
.yad eht ni ylrae os gnimmuls ereh tuo gniod uoy era tahw ,lap ,sicnarF" gniyas dna sicnarF ot gninrut
".hguoht redrum a timmoc ot t'nsaw tI
.senutrof s'rehtaf sih gniniur rof eno demalb eh esuaceb
,emit ot emit morf cisum sekam dna ,sward
.rae thgir sih fo renroc eht ni eloh llams eht deciton sicnarF os did eh sa dna
,doog yllaer leef em edam ti 'rehtorb elttil'
?flow a emoceb ot gnitnaw neeb ev'I nehw ti rof uoy nmednoc I dluoc woH .thgir lla s'tI"
.nekot ruoy em wohS"
.neht detcepxenu gnihtemos did yaJ
.erus t'nsaw eh woN
.ytic eht otni dna ssorca mih ekat teef sih tel eh
".ecnedicnioc a tsuj lla s'ti fi ro
detacilpmoc erom neve nworg dah sihT
,dias eh ",niW ,netsiL"
.tenretni eht no sa llew sa tamrof tnirp ni dehsilbup seirots sah dna
.dnim sih egnahc dluoc eh erofeb moor eht morf deirruh eh
.rehtie yrots elohw eht htiw einrE nethgirf ot tnaw t'ndid eH
.noitcerid taht ni deklaw eH
.wap s'yaJ ta deggut dna elbat eht morf pu tog eH ".kool og s'teL
.mih fo tnorf ni deraeppa ssalg eht ,rab eht dehcaer sicnarF sA
.tib a pu uoy rebos ot aet emos tsael ta deen uoy kniht I dna ,desimorp uoy hcnul taht tnaw I"
.ylthgirb dias retto eht ",etam ,sreppoc owT"
,nehw ,sruoy dah uoy dnA
.erac t'ndid eh tub
.hguone efas eb dluohs dna
.ti tuoba enoemos ot klat og ot dah eh taht dediced eh yllaniF
,elbissop sa suoires sa dnuos ot gniyrt
.slrig ton ,syob ot detcartta ma I tuB
.yldetcepxenu yllausu dna
.orevO ovitlA
,reward eht gnittuhS
swap htob htiw tuo dehcaer eH
.tuo emac gnihton tub htuom sih denepo sicnarF ".stsixe
.tekcop sih otni ti deffuts dah eh erehw elttob ydnarb eht tlef eh
",moor ym ni kcab s'ti erus ytterp m'I"
.meht fo eerht dah reve ylno I .wonk t'nod I"
.taht ekil maerd a evah dluow uoy taht" ,deerga yaJ
.os dettimda dna ,ti dnif t'ndluoc eH
.elbat eht no dehsalps raet A ".won
lluks sih fo kcab eht dehcuot tbuod fo nossirf dloc A ".erehwemos
.yldas daeh sih ekahs saw did yaJ lla tub tnemhsinup a detcepxe nooccar ehT
”gninaW nooM suobbiG“   :yojne esaelP
.won enim dnif t'nac I dnA !sdoG"
,tekcop yreve dekcehc eH .ereht t'nsaw
.gniht eno tuoba thgir saw einrE
.ti tuoba hcum wonk t'nod I"
.elihw a rof meht ta kcip t'ndid uoy fi sevlesmeht devloser smelborp
,daeh sih koohs niW ".tib
saw dias eh gniht tsrif eht dna
.erehwemos moor ym ni kcab eb tsum tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,thguoht eh ,dnuora taht yrrac ot ton tseb ebyaM
retto nA .rab ralucric eht dnuora gnidnats knuks a dna sterref wef a rof tpecxe ytpme yltsom saw hcihw ,daeH s'floW ehT deretne dna
.syad wef a rof ti nees t'nevah I hguoht
.detrons ehs ",raekcalB niW ,flesruoy ysoohc eb dluoc uoy fi sA"
.ereht delttes dna eloh a hguorht deppils dah nekot eht esac ni cirbaf retuo dna gninil eht neewteb ecaps eht neve dna
,einrE ,etam moor ym nevE
,dah meht fo rehtie sessalc tahw wonk t'ndid sicnarF
.ruoh ylrae eht fo etips ni yspit tib a yltnedive ,rood eht tuo emac elpuoc nooccar a nehw
.devil yeht erehw ron
.yawa mih dereets lrig eht sa wap a gnivaw ,dias niW ",eyB"
.yllufepoh ,deksa sicnarF "?rediC" "?evah uoy ll'tahW"
swodniw pohs eht desworb eh ,daetsnI
.kcap eht rof gnihtyna od dluoc uoy evorp ot ksat tluciffid ruoy uoy evig ot gniog saw eH
.pleh lliw ti ebyam dna"
,gninaW nooM suobbiG
.mra eht no flow eht dettap eH
.elbissop thguoht evah reve dluoc eh naht
.flU nafetS a saw yllaer erehT
.gnissarrabme os s'ti ,ti yas t'nac I" .ereht deppots yaJ "...ot
.eert wolloh taht ni eldnub gniraeppasid eht htiw secneirepxe ddo sih dna
,sih sah llits niW erus m'I
.ti dellif dna pat a rednu ssalg a devohs eh sa
,setirw eH .rettam oN
.won no kcab llaf ot enoemos evah thgim eh
,nottahC ot egdirb eht rof dedaeh dna denrut eh oS
.yawyna ekoj nuf a eb
sicnarF dewollof yltneidebo dna ,pu doots eH ".tluaf
.yaJ ot klat ot deen I"
"?taht od uoy dluow yhW"
,derewsna peekrab eht ",dal ,nosaes eht siT'"
.mra s'niW ta deggut lrig ehT .derewsna niW
nrevat eht fo tuo
.ereh edisni mih tfel tsuj eW .ysae s'taht ,hO"
"...ereh fo tuo klaw tsuj ot ton doog os neeb ev'uoY
.evah thgim yeht revetahw ro redic a rof hguone naht erom eb ylbaborp dluow hcihw
.tuo gniht siht erugif ot evah ew tsrif tuB"
,ylekilnu os demees tI
.ekoj a rof gnihtyna od lliw niW"
.dekrep srae sih dna deknilb flow ehT ".uoy
.lrig eht ta dennirg neht dna
,won rebmemer I tub ,neht ecnis tnew ti erehw wonk t'nod I"
.ohR atE ahplA on si yllaer erehT" .dias eh
.toof yb yawa syad owt yal taht nwot rellams hcum a ,llirnuS morf emac eH
.tuo tnew I erofeb gninrom siht ti dah llits I wonk I tuB
derewsna retto eht ",ris ,uoy knahT"
,swap sih ni ecaf sih dih yaJ
?ti gniwonk tuohtiw redrum a timmoc ot sa yldab os derutcarf evah yllaer eh dluoC
,ebij siht derongi raekcalB ".tcaf
.dehgual ylno lrig ehT ".retteb
".yrutnec a naht erom rof tcnitxe neeb sah puorg eht ecnis ,ti detairporppa fo tros tsuj I"
.yltcefrep sehctam dnuof yeht gniht eht fo noitpircsed ehT
.sicnarF ot ti dewohs dna tekcop tsev sih otni dehcaer eH
krow egelloc fo erusserp eht rednu gnikaerb stneduts fo draeh dah eH
,hsipeehs dekool yaJ
.melborp elttil siht evah I"
.su rof gnikool semoc hctaw eht fi ,ti ecudorp ot elba eb uoy taht tnatropmi eb dluoc tI" .deksa yaJ "?erehW"
.tuo taht derugif evah ot smees
"?enecs emirc eht ta dnuof hctaw eht eno ehT
.kral a rof ti htiw gnola tnew tub
.dias eh ",ecno ohR atE ahplA na saw yllaer erehT"
"?morf emoc lla yeht did erehW ?snekot eht dna egdelp ehT ?koob ehT
"?snooccar htiw setad uoy teg ot rekaerb eci nA ?no emoc
,smees ti ,reed detah yllaer ,yllaer eH
.eganam nac flow a sa os hcum sa
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
ytlucaf dna stneduts ot deretac egdirb eht dnuora yletaidemmi aera eht tub
.desluper ton tub ,desirprus yrev saw sicnarF
.tiaw dna tnemtnioppa na ekam ot evah ylbaborp d'eh tub
.ytic eht fo trap rehto emos morf emoc tsum dna ,lla ta stneduts ekil kool ton did meht fo rebmun riaf a taht gniciton
neffits ot demees flow eht tub ,niaga gniyrc trats ot gniog saw eh thguoht sicnarF dna delffins yaJ
"?wonk uoy od woH" .flow eht ta derats sicnarF "?tahW"
.uoy ot detcartta gnileef fo tros saw I esuaceb em htiw sessem yllaer siht ,yldnoceS
,dias eh ",yaJ ,gnihtemos uoy llet ll'I"
,teerts eht no sklof rehto eht ta dekool dna
.meht ni tfel 'sicnarF koot dna
.emit gnol a etiuq rof ereht tas sicnarF
.hguoht ,sessalom tlips revo gniyrc esu oN
.flow kcalb lla ,egral yrev a saw yllaer eH
.esnopser s'flow eht saw
.daeh sih koohs flow ehT
,wap rehto eht nO
.rufeltneg deltit emos gnitulas fi sa rae sih dehcuot dna
,yfsitas ot dnamed ysae na siht gniknihT ".nekot
.sgniht owt rof tpecxe ynnuf yrev eb dluow sihT"
.deerga flow eht ",thgir llA"
".rehto eht naht esrow si su fo rehtien tub ,egnarts eb htob yam eW
.yltpurba dias eh ",si ti erehw wonk I teb ll'I"
".sknaht dna ,era uoy
".os ro 643 ni kcab
.eb dluow ti dias maerd ym ni flU erehw eert wolloh eht ni saw ti revetahw ro efink taht dnif did yllaer I dna
.mih htiw od ot gnihton detnaw dna ,flow a saw ehS
",taht lla gniwonk fo yaw yna dah reven I dnA"
.seye sih revo wap thgir sih debbur sicnarF
,daeh nedoow devrac A
.elbisnopser m'I fi wonk t'nod I"
.stsixe llits ti taht gnidneterp neeb ylno ev'I
.ylthgit kcab srae sih gnidlof
,nmutua etal fo llihc gnipoleved ylwen eht tsniaga no tekcaj sih dellup nooccar eht sA
?ereht neeb ti daH
",gnihtemos uoy llet ot tog ev'I ,yaJ ,netsiL"