,eciohc tsrif ym yllaer t’nsaW“
.yletal ti gnileef yllaer toN“ .deggurhs retniW
,leehw gnireets eht morf daeh reh tfil tsael yrev eht ta dluohs
,leehw gnireets eht tsniaga gnitser daeherof
.diov eht otni gnirelloh ekil leef ot gnitrats saw tI
,etor emaceb sdleif mrof ni niaga noitamrofni taht lla ni llif ot reh deriuqer neht
.noitartsurf fo tnev a tsuj ,sdrow oN
elbat nehctik eht ta delttes saw ehs ecno ylnO
”.haey ,elihw a rof ereh neeb ev’I esoppus I“
,gnivird rof semit tseb eht dnuora yad reh eludehcs ot retniW ot pu saw tI
.ecnelis ,ton naht netfo erom tub
— raluger a emoceb ot reh decnivnoc gnivah anilaM
.daeh reh koohs dna dehgual anilaM
,yllacisyhp ssorg repus gnihtyna od t’ndid eH“
erehTteG rof gnivird enoemos taht detcepxe yllareneg elpoeP
eunev trecnoc emos ot meht gnivird dna
,ti fo erutan mrof-eerf eht saw tnemyolpme fo mrof wen siht ot tifeneb tseggib eht elihW
,hguod fo gnidaenk hcum os morf nrow
.riomem aidem-dexim a ,ylla
.sthguoht s’efiw reh ta sseug t’ndluoc retniW
”?niaga boj lanoitidart erom gnihtemos rof kool thgim uoy kniht uoy oD“
,sedir eht rof lufetarg era sklof tsoM
.enola meht evael ot hguone gniod erew yeht tahw wenk
,kcatta cinap a gnivah lesaew denethgirf a ot etoyoc a htiw gnola tsipareht deyalp ,noisacco eno nO
.s’xnyl eht htiw sregnif reh eniwt ot pot retnuoc eht ssorca wap reh dils dna
.tsrub dah mad eht retfa toN .won toN
.rof deifilauq saw ehs ksat a ro pu porc ot edir a rehtie rof gnitiaw
.hguoht ,cipot eht pord t’ndluoc ehS
.pu nesool ot elba ehs saw
,neercs eht ta debmuht dna
,yppah erew yeht dnA
.klus reporp a saw sihT
stnemucod dennacs morf yrtne atad gnimrofrep enoemos htiw os toN
”.revird a sa efas yats ot woh ,ekil ,fo esnopser dennac a em tnes tsuj yehT“
.toidi na dellac saw ehs semit ynam woh fo kcart tsol xnyl ehT
nwot fo edis rehto eht ot evord I .suovren teg d’I
maerc deppihw rof tnahcnep s’retniW no pu dekcip evah ot demees anilaM
,dias uoy ekil tub ,eeffoc rof lufetarg era elpoep fo tol A .haeY“ ”?yltsoM“
gnihtemos saw taht dnoyeb dereffo ti tahW
,sgnitsop hguorht gnilworp ruoh na gnidneps ,stfihs ni krow dluow ehS
.delworg xnyl eht
.lley feirb a tuo tel ehs dna ,deodnecserc ,esor
”?anilaM roF ?retniW“ #
ot deirT .evitisop dnuos ot deirt
”.did eh esle gnihtyreve tsuj saw ti tub
rethgiarts pu tas
gnol…tsuj I .nirtaK ,yrros m’I“
,noitacilppa rehtona tey no timbus kcilc dluow ehS
”.ksatelpmiS no sgig modnar dna sihT
,edir a tpecca ot og d’I emit yrevE
— tekram eht ot nruter ot evah won d’ehs sehtolc
.doirep ecarg yad-eerht eht gnirud tcejorp eht detelpmoc dah ehs retfa nwardhtiw ti evah ot ylno
.wols ylriaf s’tI .eruS“ ”?won ,tahW“
.ti deniager dah ehs litnu
.reh morf yawa ylhtooms delgna tsniaga gninael saw ehs rood eht
.detalernu neht dnA
.elbaturcsni os syawla saw xof ehT
.denepeed nworf s’anilaM
.esac reh depleh ylniatrec
,sisab ton-ro-toh fo tros a no srevird gniweiver rof etis a s’ereht yltnerappA“
.slennahc noitacilppa lausu eht fo lla tsuahxe ot keew a flesreh tes dah ehS
.llet t’ndluoc ehs ,yadoT
.ht31 drawot kcab daor eht nwod detrats dna
dna nwot reh ot lacol htob ,sdraob gnitsop boj ot detcidda werg retniW ,daetsnI
.sriats eht pu daeh dluohs ehS
.nwo reh ni ezeeuqs a sregnif esoht evag dna dehgis retniW ”.yako s’tI“ ”.evol ,yrros m’I .dnatsrednu I“
— naeB eht dna kooB ehT ta potpal reh no kcuts eb dluow ehs ,syad emos dnA
eht tuoba gnihtemoS ”?tsael ta ,retteb yna uoy gnitaert ksatelpmiS sI
.skeew wef tsal eht rof ’yad gnol‘ retfa ’yad gnol‘ gnivah neeb evah uoY
,hu…yleugav eseht lla gniyas tpek dna tnorf pu gnittis tuoba yhsup yllaer tog tsuj eH
.yawa enohp tuP .egassem deteleD
snaf strops deretsalp ro sreppoh-rab yspit gnipeek yb ecivres fo tros a gniod saw ehS
,meht dnuora no stup eno taht ksam liater yppah fo tros eht ta doog tog I
,ecaf taht daer ot elba eb dluow edewS rehtona spahreP
.teiuq gnieb ylpmis yllareneg yad dab a gnivah sklof fo ecneirepxe reh did sa
.reggib leef enoemos ekam ot
.daeh reh koohs retniW ”?gnivirD
pohs eht ni s’raC
.skcolb owt txen eht klaw dna
,dil eht desolc dna deggurhs neht
.erawrevlis reh nwod tup yllanif xof eht nehw noitnetta lluf s’nirtaK dah ehs wenk ehS
.yaw nwo rieht ni
.gnieesnu ,nexiv eht ta
.epyt eht s’taht ,peY“
”.ruoh hsur gnineve neht dna ,sksat erom ,hcnul gnirud gnivird ,sksat emos gniod
.dekil evah dluow ehs naht reitlas spahrep hguoht
.enohp reh hguorht debmuht taes kcab eht ni regdab eht dna
.ot klat ot ysae emaceb
.elppir ecafrus eht no mrof ot gnitrats saw taht niks eht gnihctaw
# ?ehs t’ndid ,sllib eht yap ot dah ehs ,llitS
.meht hguorht gnihcnurc swap daorb s’xnyl eht
,gnol a retfa dias ehs ”,thgir er’uoY“
?ekil uoy od ti tuoba tahW ?haey hO“
,sknird fo deen ni eno on gniees
.gnihtemos ro llacer trap A .sgniht ytnarraw esoht fo enO
.ton dluoc sgig eht taht ytilibats fo esnes a tnael tI .elbignat ssel
,ti morf dluoc ti lla daer ot desimorp taht
.luos eht no reisae eb dluow srebmun fo daetsni elpoep was I erehw ot gnivom derugif I
.kcab eht morf eciov detcartsid a emac ”?uoy tuoba woH“
esoht ,eson kcalb-hctip eht ylno htiw detautcnup
.sklawedis rof doom a t’nsaw siht tub
,gnorw em teg t’nod ,yako s’tI“
,nwod enohp reh tes ,rood eht nepo dluohs ehS
.ecrof lluf ni dna
”.laed a fo gib taht eb t’ndluow ti derugif I os ,krow morf ecnatsid gniklaw nihtiw m’I
nrut tfel a detaitogen retniW sa ecnelis fo stnemom wef a erew erehT ”.lla ta toN“
wodniw eht tuo yllud dekool retniW
,ylfeirb potpal reh ta depyt ehS
”?tsaf os klim hguorht og uoy taht ,krow uoy od erehW .hguone riaF“
rac eht dekcol dna tuhs yeht ,rehtegoT
,siht ekil ffuts rof diap teg nac uoy dalg m’I
.ti fo kcis tog tub ,ecnanif ni krow ot desu I
”sgiG“   :yojne esaelP
doom a t’nsaw sihT
.esoppus I“ .denworf retniW
.dnik tnereffid A
.yldetcartsid sregnif eht fo ezeeuqs taht denruter retniW ”.evol ,yrros m’I“
”?ti tuoba od nac erehTteG taht gnihtyna erehT“
,eurt dleh sedir rof lufetarg gnieb sklof fo ecneirepxe reH
”.hguoht ,ssupruos a tsuj er’uoy kniht I
.deunitnoc ehs ,os od ot hguone dehsinif dah ehs nehW
,elbigilletninu hgin ,duol yllufniap gnirelloh
”,htnom a neeb s’tI“
”?edisni emoc uoy nac ,retniW“
,klawedis a saw erehT
”.tsael ta ,hcum sa toN
,gnivird fo trap largetni na saw taht noitcaretni laicos decrofne eht morf kaerb a elihw
,dda ot denetsah regdab ehT ”.sruoh owt tuobA“
,detaeper ehs ”,tihS“
,emit siht tub ,noisserpxe na hcus htiw gnola tnew noitome tahw erus etiuq reven saw retniW
.yppah ylerar erew spirt regnol ffo gnitteg seilimaf dna
.deggurhs ,delims regdab ehT
”.klim hguorht gniwom trats ew dna ,tuo dloc gnitteg stratS
,redro ni erew selif reh erus gnikam setunim evif gnidneps neht
— tuo gnitset saw nirtaK epicer wen emos
— ciffart otni kcab rac eht dils retniW
.won thgir toN .retniW ton tub
,eeffoc a barg d’ehS
.noitavitom fo kcal ehT .ria fo kcal ehT
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.teerts eht nwod gnirats dna edirts-dim gnippots
”?sruoh nwo ruoy gnitteS
,pit elbaezis a yb ni derul saw ehs semit fo rebmun eht fo kcart tsol ehS
.dnes t’ndluow ehs taht
ti fo sedisni eht ta gnikop saw dna edam dah ehs sgnilpmud eht fo eno gnitcessid eb ot demees ehs
.esuap etarebiled
.anilaM morf eerht rebmun etalocohc toh gnitpecca yllufetarg
.sboj reh ni evitceles erom eb ot reh wolla ot hguone saw ti tub
,rorrim weiv-raer eht nI
,hguoht ,emit revO
”?taht od llits neve yeht oD ?neht ,renaol oN“
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,drah oot hsup t’now dna uoy evol I taht wonk uoy ,retniW“
.eeffoc reh tog ehS
,sseug I ,sgniht yxes
gnirob…gnigolatac ,noitpircsnart ,gnilif enod ev’I
,ti htiw serots lacol gnidoolf nageb ehs
”.etar siht ta ,mret gnol ti htrow s’ti fi wonk t’nod I tub
”!teg ew reisub eht ,kool ew reisub ehT .stnialpmoc oN“
.ecnelis ynots hguorht ylimaf htiw gnipoc srehtom ro
”?strihs ruoy ffo pord dna kcehcyap tsal ruoy pu kcip emoc tsuJ“
.rac reh fo kcab eht morf seirdnus rehto dna klim fo sgab eht daolnu anilaM depleh retniW
,gnikrow esaec yletelpmoc ot elba reveN
”.gnitsugsid yletelpmoc t’nerew taht fi snoitalutargnoc yas d’I“
.gninworf ,deddon xof ehT ”.yad
”.weiver sih no ti denoitnem I ,haeY“
,elbat nehctik eht ta pu gnittis fo syad eht erew enoG
.noitanitsed s’regdab eht ot reh tcerid ot vantas eht tes ot
.elbayojne thgirtuo ton fi
”.kcolb eht nwod tsuj si ,drobsgaddiM ,tnaruatser s’efiw yM
.dlot eb hturt ,hcum taht lla srevird eht tuoba erac ot mees t’nod yehT
.gniylppa sruoh owt rehtona neht
,llits doots retniW dna nirtaK
.hgual ot nrut s’retniW saw tI
# .dehctaw ehs dna ,tas ehS
ton…saw maerc deppihw eht hguorht kaerb dluow aococ eht yaw eht tuoba gnihtemoS
enohp reh no ppa erehTteG eht ta gnippat erofeb ni delkcub flesreh teg ot anilaM rof detiaw retniW ”.seirrow on ,hO“ ”.lla dna
,eno llams eht eb ot no thguorb saw ehs netfo woh fo kcart tsol ehS
”.kcab siht fo lla gniluah ton m’I tub ,ereht klaw ot hguone ysaE
.ekib ro klaw ot gnilliw erom eb dluow sklof sa ,wols yllausu erew syad mraW
.deddon nexiv ehT
,dna naeB ehT dna kooB ehT dnuora dekool anilaM ,gninworF
.serutaef esoht ot ngierof gnihtemos llits saw ereht ,tey dnA
.eno eht wonk I !haey ,hO“
.sremotsuc eht erew ereht neht dnA
,azalP teertS ht31 eht fo dne eht ta enoz gnidaol eht ot ti edam yeht ecnO
.boj wen a rof kool dluohs ehS
,delims reh fo trap renni emoS
”.htgnel eht ylpmis naht erom saw ti ekil sdnuos ti esuaceb ,raeh ot tnaw I
”.nrael ot pu eb d’I ,haeY .yrroS“
,dekrow nexiv eht elihw ecaf reh hctaw semitemos dluow retniW
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
— neeb dah s’nosnevetS sa — srecorg lacol eht fo lla htiw gnitrats
.yteirav rediw a ees ot nageb ehs
.yenom reh gnivas eb dluohs ehs ebyaM
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,edisni daeh dna rac eht fo tuo teg dluohs ehs taht wenk reh fo trap emoS
:ylekil erom erew sedir nehw semit erew ereht ,eruS
”.worromot gnikool trats ll’I“
,rac eht ni tas ehs gnol woh wonk t’nod retniW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.taes reh ni kcab denael dna
”.gnihtyna ro pu ti gnirb ot tsrif eht m’I ekil toN
.yllufeur delims nirtaK
nirtaK ot egassem rehtona tey tuo gnippat
,gnivird ruoh hsur gninrom gnikrow snaem taht em rof
hcum yap t’nseoD
.sthguoht rieht hguorht gnihcraes htob ,dewob sdaeh
.sksat ffo-eno yb derevoc eb dluow esle gnihtyna taht dna
.retfa ecaep ta erom tlef ehs sselehtenon tey dna
.dehgual dna trohs flesreh thguac retniW ”!esruoc fO“
.repapswen eht fo syad eht erew enog ,lleH
”?gnirih uoy erA .on ,llew…I“
”.tsil eht edam I sseug I dna
.cigam naivanidnacS fo tros emos ro ruf etihw-lla eht saw
.esnes sekam taht
liater tuoba dekil I sgniht tseb eht fo tol a em steg ti taht si ti tuoba ekil I gniht eht kniht I ,oN“ ,deunitnoc neht
— sehtolc reh fo tuo egnahc
.retniW ot pu dekool xof ehT
”.owt eht fo gnitseretni erom eht s’gnivird ekil sdnuoS“ .deddon anilaM
.nirtaK dna reh neewteb snoisnet desae ti ,taht naht eroM
”.hsur ruoh hcnul eb d’ti derugiF
”…haeY“ ”.yrrow tsuj I
”.laedi yltcaxe ton s’ti wonk I
,ht81 dna nedniL fo renroc eht no detatiseh ehS ”.revo eciwT“
.daerd fo ecruos a emaceb semag llabtooF
.snoitome gnitepmoc eht etipsed
ereh deppart reh gnipeek saw taht gnihtemos fo kcal eht saw ti spahreP
.eb t’ndluohS“ .dehgual anilaM
knird morf rehtehw
.krow rof nur yrecorg a od ot gnivah no gnitnuoc t’nsaw tsuj I“
.ksat tnasaelp a yldrah saw
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”sgiG“
# ”?ton yhW .ti kcuf ,lleW“
,detoof-gnorW ”.em wolloF .taerG“
.gnitartsurf s’tahT“
.eno trohs a saw evird eht ,detcepxe sA
,retniW yrrac ot hguone ton saw naeB ehT dna kooB ehT
.yppah fo dnik wen A
.lla si ,gnol artxe leef tfihs ym fo tser eht edam tsuj tI“
.daeh reh detlit xnyl eht
.gniklaw tpek ehS
,yaw rehtie tuB .thgim yehT
.doog tlef ti ,srab morf emoh sklof gnivird detrats tsrif ehs nehW
.sthgin yadrutaS dna ,yadirF ,yadsruhT
.deddon retniW .deksa ehs
.htob meht tcartsid dluow wenk ehs taht eno tub
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.yllufreehc deilper xnyl eht ”,em s’taht ,peY“
.azalp eht no ,naeB eht dna kooB ehT .pohs eeffoc A“
”.hsac fo hcnub a tuo eb ll’I dna retfa pit eht llacer tsuj ll’yeht wonk I esuaceb llew yap taht sboj rof kool t’nac I
.ecneserp detnawnu emos naht rehtar
.reh ediseb eert eht morf deltrats sdriB
.tis ot elbat s’xnyl eht ta riahc rehto eht tuo dellup
.oga gnol oot ton siht detrats tsuj I .yltcaxe toN“
,muidats ot seitrap morf snaf demagerp ylhguoroht luah d’ehs sa
og…tsuj dluow ti dna
,noitats sub dna tropria eht morf dna oot spirt gnikam detrats ehs
emit htneetpmu eht rof tuo enohp reh dellup ehS
hguoht ,sruoh dradnats ytterp krow ot yrt I“
.deneppah tahw nirtaK llet dluohs ehS
.tuo deid regna fo eralf eht ecno dias nirtaK
,seye depahs-dnomla ehT
.sgnilpmud eht fo wef a gnitae yb emit rof dellats retniW ”.esoppus I“
,lriws wols a etalocohc toh reh evag retniW
.sevlesmeht od ot tnaw t’nod tub enod tnaw elpoep sgniht modnar tsuJ“ ”?taht s’tahW“
.dnabsuh-xe reh htiw noitcaretni gnidnuos-detacilpmoc emos evah dna
.evol ,yad gnol ruoy tuoba em lleT“
.robal lainem rof evreser ni dleh yeht hcihw
,ksatelpmiS morf sksat ehT
# .sthgil drazah eht ffo gninrut dna
”?meht ekil uoy oD“
,potpal reh dna regdab eht neewteb dekool ehS
.rood eht dekcolnu dna
”.elbats erom gnihtemos rof gnikool dna sksatelpmiS gniod yltsom m’I os ,speerc fo gnirts a daH
”?llew uoy etar eh did dnA“
trap era taht sgniht elttil esoht llA
dnah a tuo dehcaer nirtaK
.dnah ta melborp eht morf yawa noitnetta s’xof eht werd yletaidemmi doof eht ot ecnerefer ,detcepxe sA
.sklof knurd eht erew lla fo tsrow ehT
.snoitisop liater-non nehT
”.tluaf ym wohemos saw ti ekil ,roivaheb elbatpeccanu tuoba metsys eht morf eton a tog I dna ,yldneirfnu saw I taht denialpmoc eH
.dehgual dna efiw reh ta dettaws retniW
.steltuo liater detaler ot hcraes reh gninedaorb neht dna
,sdap reh fo ssenesraoc eht htiw neve
.snoitome reh tcelfer ot tfel swodahs on erew ereht taht
”?evisnepxe gnihton yllufepoH“
,hcnul revo emit emos ,ruoh hsur
.yhtlaeh ton si siht tub
.lufpleh gnieb ,elpoep gniteeM
.gnitailimuh os tsuj s’tI“
.drobsgaddiM morf emocni s’nirtaK tnemelppus pleh ot yenom fo tib elttil a tsael ta no yler syawla dluoc ehS
deddon nirtaK
,pu dexif lla émusér reh tog ehs ecnO
.tsewhtroN cificaP eht ni reenigne erawtfos dna ,rotide ,rohtua na
efiw reh edam ytiruces fo kcal eht detartsurf woh dezilaer t’ndah ehS
”?mih troper uoy diD“
,srenwo ssenisub llams fo elor eht ot euqinu demees taht ytleurc fo dnarb ralucitrap a derevocsid ehS
— sgnilpmud yvaeh-llid fo etalp llams a htiw
,etihw erup fo ksam knalb eht
.boj pohs eeffoc a s’tI“
sepicer wen tuoba dehsug ehS
,tnecer tsom reh gnidulcni
.ssalg eht hguorht delffum saw eciov s’nirtaK ”?evoL“
”?yako uoy erA .ees…I“
;ecnahc eht reh evig t’ndid nirtaK tub ,regnol ereht tas evah thgim ehS
.efink a fo pit eht htiw
trap elbaturcsni eht fi ediced ot yrt dna
.sttim derruf-kciht reh ni etaciled os demees yeht
.doog saw etalocohc toh ehT
.meht retfa ni dils dna
etis a ot émusér a gnidaolpu fo tca ehT
.edir eht rof hcum os sknahT“
.retteb leef dluow noitcejer thgirtuo na nevE
”.srae lla m’I ,sgninepo boj no spit yna evah uoy fI“ .elims
.eiredaramac yekoj-ni elpmis ro
”.rethguad sih s’alyaK
.elituf leef ot gnitrats saw tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.hguoht ,naem I tahw s’taht sseug I
,llew ,dna ,draob no sreganam htob peek t’ndluoc eh dias tsuj nosnevetS .rM
.esimorp I ,hguoht ,thgirla m’I“ .regna spahreP
,retniW ,yadot ni uoy ees ot desirpruS“
pu gnikcip ,nwot revo lla trad dluow xnyl eht dna
,ygrene rehtruf yna gnirb ton did htaerb eht nehW
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,rettug eht gninil
.gab reh otni kcab ti gnippils
,pohs eeffoc eht ta ton nehw yllanoisacco evord llits ehS
.smelborp nwo rieht htiw delddir erew
sepirts lla fo sregnessap
,kcab sllac wef a erew erehT .gnibmun
”.spahrep ,gnikool htrow llits s’tI“
,pleh yna deen uoy fi wonk em teL .yakO“
.won ti gnipleh oN
”.egarevoc emos esu dluoc taht stfihs emos tog ev’eW“
kcab ylneddus erew teem sdne ekam ot gniyrt fo ecaf eht ni nwod depmat neeb dah taht snoitcaretni yliad fo
taes kcab eht otni seirecorg fo skcas wef a deluah regdab ehT ”!taerG“
.gniht a ekam t’ndluow ehs ,syad emos dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.eri rieht ksir I ro efas flesym peek t’nac I
.yltsenoh ,erus ton m’I“
.ecnelis ni tas yehT
.ksatelpmiS no erom sucof reh tel emocni dedda eht tub
.wodniw s’enoemos ni rekcits erahs edir eht deciton tsrif ehs taht
”.em ta gnirats tpek dna
,lliw fo ecrof hguorht ,dna hsur a ni tuo ti tel ehs
.ydaetsnu saw sedir dedeen snaihtootwaS nehw ,revewoH
.eno taht wonk I ,hO“ .dehgual anilaM
.ylidaer erom dehgual ehS
”.emit yna ni potS“
,etis a pu dellup
.repapswen eht ni sda detnaw-pleh gnilcric
”.yllaer ,ffuts
.azalp eht ot skcolb eviF
,gnihtoos yltcaxe
?gniht emit-lluf ruoy siht sI“
.yrrow ro nrecnoc fo eno saw ti niatrec saw ehs
.os kniht t’nod I“
.yllufthguoht dewehc dna htuom reh ni ti fo flah deppop
”.nac I tahw od ll’I
.daeh reh koohs dna dehgual retniW
tlebtaes reh delkcubnu retniW
,nepo stfihs fo htrow s’keew krow emit-lluf a evah t’nod I dna
,tnemom a rof thguoht retniW
.sremotsuc tuoba dehctib dna
ylimaf reh tisiv ot nwot ni
.ti tsniaga dekrow tifeneb yrev taht
”.sontös ,yletal esoht fo tol a rehtar gnivah neeb ev’uoY“
,eciov reh fo tuo noitcejed eht peek ot deirt retniW ”.yaw rehtiE“
.taes s’revird eht fo tuo flesreh revel pleh ot wap s’efiw reh detpecca dna
,seye nworb-tsekrad
.deddon xnyl ehT
.erehwon og dluow tI .yawa
.llew sa snoitacilppa reh fo seipoc repap ffo gnippord
.oot ,serots ni era yeht naht ereh rednik yllareneg era elpoeP
.sey ,hgih si tlas ehT“
,tner fo erahs reh revoc pleh dluow
rac reh ni kcab gnippoh erofeb devaw dna deddon xnyl ehT
”.thgir yltsom saw I
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”sgiG“ saw sihT
”.eb dluow ti thguoht I naht nuf erom yaw eb ot tuo gninrut s’ti tub
”.deneppah citamard oot gnihton yllufepoH“
smra reh dessorc anilaM
llew os thgil detcelfer ruf etihw-ettam s’nirtaK
,ruf s’efiw reh ot gnignilc gnignilc llits ruolf eht htiw nevE
,gnivird morf sknurd peek ot ecin eb yam tI
,erutseg detaluclac a neeb dah tI
keew dexob-emit reh fo dne eht sdrawot sgnituo esoht fo eno no saw tI
.htaerb peed a koot xnyl ehT
.teiuq ytterp yllausu era yad doog a gnivah t’nera taht esoht dna
,skoob ruof fo rohtua si ehS
.elacs rediw a no nar taht emos
.gnikooc trats ,pu naelc
,doof klat ot reh gnitteg
.niaga ecno pu flesreh gnidaol ,dias regdab eht
”–nrael ot gnilliw er’uoy fi tub
”.dedeen stargnoc on ,haeY“
.oN“ .decniw retniW
,gnivigsknahT dnuorA
,ylwols deknilb nirtaK
— taes eht ssim ot deganam dah god eht ,yllufknaht — sllew-toof eht fo tuo timov gninaelc tub
,potpal reh morf pu dekool xnyl ehT ”.gnol os rof dna
,dedda ehs ,elims yrw a htiW
.negyxo fo kcal ehT
dna serots ot dnuora gnivird detrats ehs ,yad htruof ro driht eht nO
,gnilpmud eht fo erutxet lanretni eht htiw deifsitas yltnerappa ,nirtaK
”.ti rof yap ot evah t’nod I tsael ta tub ,owt ro yad a rof rac a tuo m’I
# .hguoht ,uoy sa ytlas sa toN“
,tsehc reh ni detrats lworg wol A
”?nomel erom ebyaM .ytlas tib A“
.tuo rehtruf daeh ot evah I os ,sklim citoxe erom eht lles meht fo enon tub
.hgih gum siht delip dna
,revewoh ,taes kcab eht ni detimov enoemos emit tsrif ehT .daor eht ffo
.ereh ti dedeen t’nevah I tub
.detcepxe dah rehtien taht syaw ni etaresimmoc dluoc yehT
,keew eht rof emocni eht fo tnecrep ytneves ekam d’ehs ,syad emoS
”.relloh ot dnet t’nera ohw esoht
,haeY“ .dennirg anilaM
stfihs wef a taht tsurt dluoc ehS
llew sa ecivres doof ni gnikrow won saw retniW tahT
.secnerefnoc dna ,strecnoc ,stneve gnitrops fo kcart gnipeek detrats ehS
?rof ksa yeht dluoc erom tahw ,yllaer dnA
”.em ta gnirelloh elpoep ynam teg t’nod I
’ssorG‘” ”.derevocer etiuq reven dna hguorht yawtrap edir ssorg yllaer a dah tsuJ“
,htiw laed ot hguone ysae htob erew sepyt esohT
,doog etiuq erew yehT
,gnileef saw nirtaK tahw yas ot
— yadot thgil ylluficrem
.ssendoog knaht ,oN“
.yaw eht fo tuo gniyats ,naelc gnipeek rof
,nageb yeht erofeb efas neve t’nsaw ehS
”.selohssa dwel htiw kcul dab fo gnirts a tsuJ
”,gnirih gnikcuf neve s’enoyna fI“
”.em morf rehtona tseuqer t’ndluow eh erus eb ot tsuj
.ezeeuqs a rof revo s’retniW fo eno gut ot
.edisni yaw rieht edam dna
”?esruocer yna evig t’ndid yeht dnA“
.muidats supmac htootwaS-IU eht ro
.denepeed nworf esohw ,xof eht ot tnedive neeb evah tsum tI
.thgiarts gniklaw tpek dna ,duola emit siht
.tnelis yats ot eugnot reh tib retniW
.droffa regnol on dluoc ehs eeffoc a barg t’ndluohs ehs ebyam rO
,sedir htiw dedoolf eb dluow retniW ,syad emoS
”.em htiw taes tnorf eht ni pu gnittis tuoba tnamada yllaer
”,melborp a ton m’I sa gnol sA“
.wodniw edis s’revird eht ta kconk tfos a saw ereht erofeb
.krow gniod tuoba dna tuo er’uoy taht ees ot dalg m’I
.ruos ot nageb ksat eht fo noinipo reh
tfel nrut dluohs ehS .nrut dluohs ehS
sevael daed fo selip eht hguorht ylivaeh degdurt retniW .tihs ,lleW
nerdlihc elgnarw ot gniyrt srehtaf tespu yb ecno naht erom ta deppans tog ehS
”.haey ,hguoht ,thgil era sgab esoht tbuod I“ .dennirg ehS
.lla ta toN“ .dias ehs
.denediw elims s’anilaM
stneduts fo spuorg
”.niaga gnihcraes trats neht dna eseht hsinif ll’I .thgir er’uoy ,oN“
,yriad lles taht ecnatsid gniklaw nihtiw spohs wef a s’erehT
niaga ecno nexiv ehT
.regdab eht drawot ti denrut dna
.delbmurg ehs ”,flesruoy fo loof nmad a gnikaM“ .pleh t’ndid tI
.mhmM“ ”?gniht fo tros elpoep gniteem eht tsuJ
”,retniW ,niaga sknahT“
”.dnuora sexob gniggard ro yad lla gnidnats eht tuohtiw
.kni.oykam reh no
.ruf kciht ni neddih tsomla srae eht
.stneve rof seruhcorb gnikam ro
”.rab eht dniheb dnuora uoy wohs tsael ta nac I
.kcab detlit srae
.yawa kool ot reh desuac noisserpxe s’xnyl
.llam eht gnola rettup sdworc noonretfa ylrae eht hctaW
”.esimorp I .evol ,yako eb ll’tI“
tsuj saw eH“ ”?woh
,elzzum tnulb eht
.taht od neve ot deriuqer noitcnuf evitucexe eht dekcal ehs tey dna
”?eeffoc tuoba gnihtyna wonk uoy od ,lleW“
.yadot gnivird ton er’uoy desirprus tsuJ
.taht tsuJ“ .deddon xnyl ehT
# .derit saw elims reH
.ksatelpmiS no stcejorp no gnikrow rof semit tseb eht dna
.sehcneb eht fo eno no tis