?moorhtab eht ni saw eh nehw ebyaM
.hcamots reh fo nworb yddum eht rO
,noitartnecnoc ni deworruf worb a htiw yldrawkwa tahwemos dnuora doots ehS
”?thgir ,gnihtemos uoy reffo llew sa thgim I ,naem I ?ecils a ekil uoy dluoW“
,ylthgils knurhs emarf egral siH
.enohp sih ni rebmun reh tup dah ehs ,hguone eruS
.yllaer ,tol elohw a ton ,hO“
.nwod dekool eh dna
”.taht ees ot evol d’I ,kcaB sekirtS eripmE evah uoy fI
.uoy tuoba ytnelp em dlot ynneJ tub
”sknahT gniviG“:yojne esaelP
.elihw a rof em htiw yats nac uoY“
dna delims retto ehT
.enola ylrettu dna yletelpmoc
.oga tnemom a saw eh sa deticxe sa t’nsaw eh
.ydal a tnemilpmoc
”?rebmemer ,taht did ydaerlA“
gnorts dna ediw saw tsehc siH
”?uoy pleh I yam woh ,azziP s’asoR amaM“
.yawyna pu gnisolc no gninnalp erew eW .enif er’uoy ,haN“
”.retal hcum oot yats em ekam t’noD .og ot deen od I“
,reh ssik ot pu kcab devom eH
htiw dam oot eb ot stnerap ym tnaw t’nod I .dluohs I“
spih reh deyaws ehs taht erus saw eh
taht yaw a ni evitressa os saw xe esohw ,llub eht rof gnihserfer saw tI
”.ris ,melborp oN“
”.epyt lufecrof eht yltcaxe ton m’I wonk I ,naem I
.devaw dna reh ta kcab dennirg eH
,retaw eht no gninruT
”.lla retfa ,yad wols a s’tI
”.hguoht cisum tseb eht sah eripmE taht yned t’nac uoY“
s’azziP“  .mih ta pu gninnirg ,esae htiw ti thguac ehS
ynnuf ti no gnipeels morf secalp elpuoc a ni dettam saw ruf siH
.ssik taht htiw deifirev eb dluoc sdrow reh fi sa ,esnetni erom tub
.dennirg retto eht
.raey eht fo dne eht ta htiw decaf eb ylekil d’eh enif a
ecalp fo tuo eb ot tnaw t’ndid osla eh tub
.keehc sih no dnah reh
.reh ot nwod ti dessot dna ,ffo ti sih dellup dna
.eveels eht yb thguac
”?esaelp ,hU .525 moor ,llaH ecnerwaL ot dereviled ti evah I nac dnA
.kcab reh no tser wap egral sih tel eh won roF
.cificeps gnihton ,raelc gnihton tuB .ydob reh ,ecaf reh fo eniltuo na
,yks krad eht ta wodniw sih tuo dekool eh sa dehgis yraM
.ssenisub doog er’uoY
.sih ni wap reh koot dna daeh dekcoc a htiw reh ta dekool tnecniV
flesmih fo ffo retaw eht gnipiws
,llaw eht otni gnineerac meht tnes mutnemom eht taht ecrof hcus htiw reh tsniaga mih dellup dna tleb sih debbarg yraM
.ylthgils os reve gnilggiw ydob reh ,delims ehs
”.epyt taht ton er’uoy wonk I
.keew tsal morf llafwons laudiser eht fo ssenetihw eht htiw gnitsartnoc
,elpoep lausu eht fo eno ,esle enoemos eb dluow ti ,gnirewsna enohp eht no eciov eht eb t’ndluow tI
,ybigreK yb ”sknahT gniviG“
.azzip doog s’ti ,naem I .haeY“
.larehpirep sih fo tuo gnidliub eht gnivael reh was eh litnu
,sdrow ecnim t’ndid retto ehT
.ylhsipeehs daeh sih deddon eH
”.gnihtemos dias evah dluohs ehs ,smelborp dah ehs fI
ssalc morf srepap dna gnissot ot dnuora nettog reven d’eh taht slaem suoiverp morf sexob erew ereht ,erehwyreve tuoba nwerts erew sehtolc siH
.eb ot tuo ti ekam thgim sonrop ekil snoissap gnihsarc dna sdnah dna noitom fo ynohpocac a t’nsaw tI
,gniog saw yad sih woh fo noitacidni tcefrep eht t’nsaw noitseuq eht fI
.lrig elttil a sa em rof tol a tnaem tI“
.esle gnihtemos saw elims taht tuB
.rehtegot emit dneps dluoc ew thguoht tsuj I“
eb ot gnidnamed ,noitatirri ni delworg hcamots s’llub ehT
.tib a dehsulb ehs dna tnew sih erehw was seye reH
”!hguoht senil yseehc ynam os sah tI“ .denaorg eH
.dnah elgnis a htiw pu reh detfeh dna doots tnecniV
.0102 ecnis sdrapoel dna shateehc neewteb ecnereffid eht gninialpxe dna krow yrruf gnitirw neeb s’eH
.deirruh eh fi rewohs eht ni ffo esnir ot emit hguone evah d’eH
.reh rof tuo gab reh fo parts eht gnidloh ,dereffo tnecniV
”.ecalp eht pu gniknits em tnaw t’nod uoy fi egnahc nac I .yllautca ,gab ym ni sehtolc fo riap artxe na tog ev’I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.uoy peek em tel t’nod tuB
taht hsilpmocca dluoc retto ytfarc eht woh revo dellum eH
”,reh ssik ot uoy stnaw ehs fi rednow I“  .hcuot ton dna
”.spil ym ot esolc yrev s’ehs dna ,em no retto etuc a evah I taht gnikniht m’I“
ot yaW“ .ti no dewehc dna hteet sih neewteb ti thguac eH
,mih drawot pets a koot dna pu doots yraM
”,yawyna taht fo lla od ot dedeen I .revetahW“
,daeh sih koohs tnecniV
.tem spil rieht dna
,hO“ .swalc llud htiw daeh reh gnihctarcs ,ffo tah krow reh dellup dna
,ni denael tnecniV dna delims yraM
riah sih hguorht sdnah reh nar ehS
.doog ,gnihtemos ni poP“
”.ffo stnap ruoy teg neve dluoc uoy erofeb roolf eht no uoy evah d’I ,gnihtyna deirt uoy fi ,sediseB
.tuo gnippets dna ffo retaw eht gninrut ,delbmurg eh
.riap naelc ,wen a ni saw ehs ,retal tnemom A
.erofeb was eh ruf tfos eht gnileef
.retaews dedracsid reh barg ot mih fo og tel ehs nehw dias eh ”,gniht emit-eno a eb ton retteb sihT“
”.eno txen eht teg ot uoy tcepxe I tuB
.ereht reh gninnip mih htiw
,erac sih fo ewa ni saw yraM
”.flesym tol a III edosipE ekil I
.os did eh sa reh dloh ot
?eciov eht sserpmi ot denimreted os eh saw yhW
eh dna ecaf s’tnecniV dedoolf roloc eroM
,gnivigsknahT no ,tas eh moor mrod sih ni ,saw rettam eht fo tcaf daS
”.ssa ym ta gnirats potS“
.yddig tsomla leef mih edam kcab sih dniheb esiarp fo dnik taht gnitteg tub
,ni detairuxul eb ot edam erew ti fi sa gnitivni dna tfos dekool ruf nworb yddum s’enirtul ehT
.ti dekcolnu dna deb sih morf enohp sih debbarg llub ehT
.retto eht ot resolc ni denael eh sa
.ecaf reh fo tnorf ni dnah a devaw dna reh ta dekool tnecniV
?mih emalb dluoc ohw tuB
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.dekcilc enohp eht ,taht htiw dnA
,srae sih otni gnidils ,yenoh ekil demees sdrow reH
.pal s’tnecniV no nwod tis ot devom dna eceip reh ffo dehsilop yraM
trihs sih ot snottub eht nwod deliart sregnif siH
”.wonk uoy ,rebmun ruoy em evag reven uoY“
,setalp sih fo eno pu dekcip dna delggig ehS
.hcrul hcamots sih edam syawla taht yromem a saw esroh a yb dessik gnieb naitamlaD eht fo thgis ehT
,reh leef ,reh etsat ot
hcamots talf sih etipsed dna
”?uoy t’nod ,og ot deen uoY“
?ti od eh did yhw oS
.trihs detaoc-ruolf reh htiw mih detlep ehs nehw devomer ylkciuq saw ti tub dekrims eH
.ylevitcnitsni sih tsniaga gnillor spih reh
.os ro setunim 02 tuoba eb ll’tI“ ”.esruoc fo ,thgiR“
,iH“  .eciov ylbbub ,yreehc a diaS
.ynapmoc mih gnipeek saw tsuj ehS
.xob eht ediseb nwod elttob eht gnittes ,dias ehs
.ssik eht ekorb eh sa kcab reh no tuo reh gniyal ,snoitisop rieht deppilf eH
.deggurhs dna tsehc sih no swap reh htiw erom tib a pu tas yraM
…ekil tlef tahw retfa ssik eht ekorb meht fo hcaE
.seert eht hguorht taeb dna deppihw dniw eht ,edistuO
.erus eb ot ytterp yrev hguoht ,nialp
.yllufyalp gnitnilg seye reh
.ffo retaews reh dellup dna deddon yraM
,mih deredro yraM ”,stnap ym fo tuo sdnah ruoy peek tsuJ“
,noisserpmi taht tog syawla eh
?ekoC fo retiL-2 ,hU“
worb deworruf sih ta gnikool
”?gnihtemos tuoba gnikniht uoy erA“
.srebmun eht ni dehcnup dna enohp sih debbarg dnah siH ”.uoy deef ll’I“
.nwod dekool ehs dna enod litnu deknip skeehc s’retto ehT
”.dial uoy teg pleh taht ekil senil fi rednow I
?sraey ,sruoh ,setunim
…demees ehs tub ,reve nosrep tsettoh eht ro ,gninnuts t’nsaw ehS
dehcatta DI sih htiw draynal eht debbarg eH
.etad tsrif eht rof gniyap em sa ti fo knihT“
.azzip egasuas dna inoreppep egral a rof redro na ecalp ot detnaw I
”?thginot rof snalp ruoy era tahw ,oS“
.spahrep ,neeb evah dluohs eh naht reippah
”,emosdnah ,yaw eht no
,deb sih no nwod tas retto eht sa yrd gnileef taorht ,dias tnecniV ”,haeY“
.haey ,gnireffo er’uoy fi ,lleW“
,ruolf eht llems dluoc tnecniV ,saw eh erehw morF
.dneirfyob tseb eht syawla t’nsaw I llew ,haeY“
.VT sih hguorht deralb erocs eht sa nageb stiderc ehT
.depoord srae siH .mih dedihc ehs
;pu gnignah mlif wen eht ot nwodtnuoc a dna ygolirt lanigiro eht fo sretsop eht dah llub eht taht neviG
”.dnilb saw I naem t’nseod ynneJ gnitad saw I esuaceb tsuJ
,dnuora yats ot detpo eh ,oS
”?uoy era ,ssenyhs rof hcum toN“
teg dluoc yeht esolc woh htiw mih gnitnuat
.srennam fo ecnarbmemer etunim-tsal
.weiv morf ksed sih gnidih
.yawa tfird thgim ehs fi sa ,thgit sreh gnidloh sdnah sih ,deksa tnecniV
”.uoy ot ereht pu thgir ti ekat ll’I
.hcuot reh ta lausu naht redrah gnikrow traeh gnitaeb sih gnileef
.ruolf ekil tib a llems moor ruoy ekam yam I .hO“
;revo reh dekool eH
.hsulb ot nrut reh saw ti ,emit siht dna gnikwag mih thguac ehS
.deb eht ot revo retiL-2 dna xob azzip eht thguorb dna pu mlif eht tes eh
.elims yls a htiw mih dereffo ehs ”?llihC dna xilfteN“
,erofeb naht erom neve dnA
semit ynam os hguorht gnilcyc neeb dah csid eht ot unem niam eht dna won yletelpmoc nellaf dah nus ehT
sih ta delggig eciov ehT
.taht nialpxe dluow tahT“
.ssenisub ’srelggarts eht teg dna yrt ot aedi doog a eb thgim ti thguoht yeht dna ecalp eht nur stnerap ym ,haeY“  .deddorp eH
wodniw nepo eht hguorht ni dehsur sroodtuo eht fo ria looc eht nehw saw tI
,trihs sih ni senil gnitaerc kcab sih nwod nar swalc reH
.ti evah dluow eh taht suoivbo saw ti
”?I t’nod ,ffo trihs ruoy htiw deb ym no uoy evah I“
.dekniw dna seye eht ni mih dekool ehS
.tnemssarrabme ni derewol daeh sih
”?ti ekat I ,sessalc esnefed-fles koot uoY“
.taorht sih ni pmul eht dnuora ot elbanu flesmih dnuof tub wollaws ot deirt tnecniV
.roolf sih no moor hsart eht rof ffo koot dna nachsart eht ni meht devohs
.tnecsed sti nageb nus eht sa won rekrad tib a saw yks ehT
.gniunitnoc erofeb ereht llits saw eh fi gniksa
.senot yppah tub ,eltneg rieht htiw dnim sih gniflugne dna drawrof gnihsup
.mih ot klat ot ylimaf htiw ysub oot erew sdneirf sih lla dna yadot lla ta enoyna nees t’ndah eH
.ylsuorogiv deddon ehS
.emosdnah ,em eveileB“
.nwod ti tes ehs dna
”.eivom a ni pop nac eW
.rehtegot dexim lla tnarodoed reh dna taews reh
.mih ot od dluow xe sih dnuora nees reve ylno d’eh retto lufituaeb siht tahw fo erusnu ;tnemom a rof deltsirb eh dna
*** .thguoht eh naht yad retteb hcum a eb dluow siht
.saw ti hguoht esucxe ysmilF
.tsael ta ,eromyna toN .flesmih rof pu gnidnats ni diarfa t’nsaw eh ,hguohT
.htiw yawa enod ylkciuq erew
.shtaerb reh htiw gniknirhs dna gnidnapxe kcab s’yraM
.htrow saw taht tahw rof ,oot mih ekil ot demees ehs dnA
nwod ecils eht gnippolp
.dennirg dna mih ta pu dekool ehS
”,eno etirovaf ym ylisae s’tahT“
”.hguoht em rof rood eht kcolnu ot uoy deen ll’I .ris ,esruoc fO“
.taht htiw yawa teg mih tel dluow sdneirf sih gnipoh dna
”?gnivigsknahT no gnikrow er’uoy ,llits tuB
.esoprup a htiw gnihcram dna remraw azzip a gnidloh retto railimaf a was eh taht
.seye gniteem seye
.ttub etuc reh ot deulg eye sih ,erom hcum
deb sih no deggel-ssorc tas ehS
,mih dekil dah stnerap reh desirprus t’nsaw tnecniV
,mih ot resolc retto eht sserp ot gnitnaw flesmih dnuof dna deddon eH
.stnap reh no skram emas eht ees tub pleh ton won dluoc tnecniV dna smra reh htiw esor taht trihs krow derettalps-ruolf a erow ehs htaeneB
dessarrabme saw tnecniV
,sllaw sih ta dekop dna deparcs snroh siH
”,hcum yrev uoy knaht ,thgirlA“
,yawa ekorb yllanif ehS
:yraM morf saw txet ehT
”.esaelp I sa od ot eerf m’I oS .won revo s’tfihs ym ,tuB .did uoy tahT“
.erugif reh fo erom tib a tsuj ees mih gnittel
”,uoy gnissik ton etah ydaerla I esuaceB .dooG“
”,niaga uoy ees ot tnaw I
,ruf eht hguorht regnif a dehsurb ehs
tahwemos reh thguoht eh
.seye dnik htiw mih ta gnikool
,deksa ehs ”?weiv eht ekiL“
no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”.taht htiw yppah ton llits m’I .lla ta riaf on saw uoy ot did ehs tahw taht wonk od I dnA
.cirbaf eht hguorht raet t’ndluoc ehs fi neve
,thguoht eht detaicerppa dna sreffo eht rof lufetarg ,esruoc fo ,saw eH
.enog era sdneirf ym lla dna yawa raf s’ylimaf yM“
.tnemom a rof htuom sih morf tuo gnitrad eugnot sih ,keehc reh nwod dnah a nar dna delims eH
pets hcae htiw deyahsas spih reh sa gniggaw eb tsomla ot demees reddur taht yaw eht saw tI
.mih ta dnah a dednetxe ehS
.gnivigsknahT rof nepo saw nwot ni ecalp azzip etirovaf sih taht saw derevocsid yltnecer ylno tnecniV tahW
.mmM“  .wolga serutaef sih ,dias tnecniV
”?thginot enola lla er’uoy oS“
.etib a koot dna ,flesmih eceip
”.dnim ym dessorc dah thguoht eht ,naem I“
llems a saw erehT
,trohs eno siht ,ssik rehtona rof ni gninael ,dias eh
.delims dna mih ta pu dekool ehS
”,etucyllaereruoywonktnodI
”!enohp ruoy kcehC“  .mih ot kcab
.eciton ot ton mih rof elbissopmi ti edam taht yaw a hcus ni gniyaws reddur reh
.uoy edam syadiloh eht rof rotisiv a gnieb gnihtemos—
.daeh sih koohs dna seye sih dellor eH
,pot eht ta ecal fo tops tseinit eht dah dna kcalb saw arb reH .neve deroda dna
.dedda ehs erofeb tnemom a rof ria eht ni gnuh taht ecnelis a saw erehT
,tsehc sih ot dna hcamots sih pu gninnur wap reh ,dias ehs
…dna doof sih teg dluoc eh os rood eht nepo ot dedeen eh tub
.denetsil eh ,emit sihT
.ecaf delttom s’tnecniV dellif roloC
.hguoht gnimrofsnart reh no hsurc sih tlef eh tsaf woh detah eH
,noitinifed fo esnes yna ni gnikcal
.neht ni teg nac I os DI ruoy em ssoT“
.taorht sih ni pmul eht tnemilpmoc ot htuom sih ni pmul a
.llew sa stnap sih gnisol ylkciuq ,ffo ti dellup dna
.kcep tfos a eson sih evig ot nwod denael
.setunim wef a tsuj naht regnol neeb ylraelc dah ycamitni rieht wenk eh os
.suovren ylneddus
”.rebmemer t’nod uoy esac ni ,yaw eht yb ,yraM m’I“
”.ti etah yllaer ot elbanu em sekam taht ti tuoba gnihtemos s’ereht tub ,smelborp sah ti wonk I .wonk t’nod I
hguot eb dluow sgnivigsknahT taht gnileef a dah eh ,erehwon fo elddim eht ni loohcs eht ot emac eh nehW
.meht neewteb ecaps fo hcni yreve detaemrep ecneliS
eltneg os eno hcae
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”?siht deredro ohw nosrep eht uoy erA“
.mih dlot ehs ”,gab ym em dnaH“
”?gnihtemos ot pu uoY“
,derepsihw yraM
,trihs reh rednu sdnah sih nar eH .eltneg
.sdeen reh ot dnet t’ndid I wonk I
,flesym fo erac ekat ot woh wonk I ,haeY“
.reh ot mih gniward saw retto eht tuoba gnihtemoS
”?I t’ndid ,deredro I ,lleW“
.yad taht tlef eh sseniraerd dna emirg eht yawa gnihsaw
.mih dnuora sgel reh parw ot reh tfel dna
”?niaga em ees reven ll’uoy diarfA ?yhW“
ydob reh fo edis rehtie no dekop snroh s’tnecniV
,nroh sih morf gnuh tI
”.suoedih yltcaxe ton er’uoy ,naem I“
.spil reh ot gnitniop dna
.gnihsulb llits ,yawa daeh reh denrut dna
llaw eht ot dexiffa d’eh kooh eht no pu lewot sih gnuh eh ,llits tuB
.etib a koot dna edam d’ehs azzip eht fo ecils a barg ot elzzum sih revo gnirevoh
.krow ta desu eh taht snoitulos gninaelc eht dna taews ekil dellems eh ,eson nwo sih morf llet dluoc eh ,dna
”.yadot nepo deyats ew nosaer eht flah er’uoy kniht I
.sthguoht sih morf mih koohs rood eht no kconk ehT
a debbarg tnecniV  .deb sih no tops reh gnimialcer dna
?enohp eht no eciov eht ecudeS ?tahw dnA
.stnap reh evomer ot doots ehs nehw yawa dekool dna ,taht ta detrons ylno tnecniV
.xe s’tnecniV saw ynneJ
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.keehc sih ot ssik a sserp ot ni denael ehs dna delkcuhc llub ehT
.riahc ,elbatrofmocnu rehtar dna
”,ton ro gnikrow s’ti fi erus toN
.taht dnatsrednu yletinifed nac I
,dedivorp s’mrod eht no nwod tas eh erofeb gnilims ,taht ta dehgual tnecniV
nosaer a sa loohcs ro krow gnitic
.dnah egral a htiw ecaf sih debbur dna eson sih hguorht tuo tnioppasid sih dehgis eH .reh toN .sserpmi ot eno on
.htuom sih tfel ti retfa neve retteb ecnetnes taht ekam ot gniyrt
,niaga yraM ta dekool eh nehW
.ti dlot eh ”,thgirla ,thgirlA“  .def
,resolc desserp dna decnad seidob riehT
.ti yojne t’nod uoy ekil ,hO“
,dias tnecniV ”?I did ,azzip eht rof uoy diap reven I“ .yawa llup ot detrats dna moor sih ot rood eht denepo ehS .sih hctac did wap reh hguoht ,reh morf yawa deppils dna ylhsipeehs delims tnecniV
drawrof denael tnecniV  .tuhs seye reh
.modgnik regaem sih ta dekool dna retal stnemom moor eht otni kcab degrab eH
,resolc ni denael retto ehT
shgiht sih no detser ttub reH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,deb sih otno deppolp dna pal sih fo ffo dils ehs elihW
.ecaf reh gnirucsbo riah
.yrtnuoc eht fo edis rehto eht no ylimaf ot emoh teg dna yrt ot mih rof ti htrow t’nsaw ti ,yltsenoh ,taht trohs os saw kaerb sih dna
,tnessa na derumrum ehS
.azzip eht ot derutseg ehs
”?ti etah uoy nac woH .emeht s’ytiC duolC
.tsehc s’llub eht no yal retto ehT
,taht ta detrons ehS
.nwod meht gnidils ,snaej reh ot nottub eht didnu dna etib rehtona koot ehS
,desuap edosipe txen eht sa dehgis tnecniV   ybigreK yb
”?ynapmoc emos tnaw uoy oD“
,luferac eugnot gnihsarc dna spil gnicnad hcae ,dessik owt eht ,daetsnI
.rehtie gnidnamed eb ot mees t’ndid ehs tub
,egral yllarutan saw tnecniV  .ni deppets eh
.ecneserp yrev sti htiw ecaf sih ssorca ssik ot demees taht htaerb eht dna ydob mraw reh leef dluoc eH
.dehgis dna rorrim eht ni flesmih ta dekool eH
si yrots s’yadot dna
”?siht tup ot em tnaw uoy od erehW“
?mih fo tahw tub ,won retteb hcum demees tI
”,tfos os si ruf ruoY“
”.oga htnom a saw su rof gnivigsknahT .naidanaC m’I
.dworc a ni dekoolrevo eb tsomla dluoc taht ecaf nialp dna ydob ehtil reh ta gnikool seye sih
.thgir s’ehs sseug I ,haeY“
.yawa klaw ot denrut ehs nehw dias tnecniV
.suoixna mih edam ti tuoba gniraeh yltsenoh tub gnivigsknahT rof sdneirf elpuoc a htiw og ot sreffo dah tnecniV ,eruS
,sreh ot pu ecaf sih detlit ehS
erofeb dah ehs taht sllub fo snoiton deviecnocerp revetahw taht
.ot degnoleb eciov taht ohw ezisatnaf tub pleh t’ndluoc tnecniV  ”?esle gnihtynA“
.daeh sih ni kcits ot demees enil taht pukaerb eht retfa ylno saw tI
.uoy nettogrof ylbissop evah dluoc I ekil taht yas uoY“
,erugif gnitaerter reh ees ot wodniw eht tuo dereep eh nehW
.ylkciuq os ffo gnitfird dnim sih ,tuo derettups tnecniV
.sreh ot esolc ecaf sih
”.remotsuc tseb rieht htiw erew uoy meht lleT“ ”.em
.wodniw a nepo ot dah eh ,azzip eht dereviled ohw fo sseldrager taht wenk eh dna
.llaf t’ndid ehs os reh gnitroppus fo esiug eht rednu kcab reh tsniaga gnibbur wap sih ,reh deksa eh
tcaf a gnitats rO .thguohtretfa na naht erom gnihton saw ti ekil trap tsal taht ffo delttar eh
”,tnaw uoy fi ,lleW“
.loohcs siht ta eno was eh reve fi ytirar A .eniuneg
?uoy ekil stnerap ym taht wonk uoy diD …llew haeY“
llet ydaerla dluoc tnecniV
,taht ta dekrims ehS
.retto etitep ,ylbbub eht saw ereht dna ti denepo eH
,reh ta delims eH
.won thgir ti tuoba yrrow t’ndid eh tuB
,erew shtgnerts sih tahw wenk llub ehT .kaew t’nsaw eh
mraw leef ydob elohw reh edam taht sehcuot eltneg ,luferac sih
.hcamots erab reh esopxe ot hguone tsuj pu trihs reh dellup eh dna
.krow ot tnew dna depirg eh ”,tihS“
…saw eh dna moor sih ot yaw sih no retto ytterp siht saw ereH
.roolf eht otno gel erab tes eh nehw moorhtab eht fo elit eht no dekcalc sevooh s’tnecniV
;eugnot sih no ereht tas etib eht dna ffo trihs reh gnillup saw ehs taht deciton eh
.mih rof hguone doog saw taht dna
.saw tahw wonk t’ndid eh neht
…dna nuf yllaer saw tI .emit tsrif eht rof emutsoc ni ti ees ot tog I
.moor eht deyevrus dna
.sgniht ni pu tpews siht gnitteg rof flesmih htiw deyonna
.ot noitnetta diap taht
”.tnaw uoy fi-I“ .deggurhs ylerem
”.gnihtemos gniod ffo era elpoep tsom ,dias uoy sA
.did tsuj eh gnihtyreve enod evah ot nosaer laer a t’nsaw erehT
.pu revoc ot gnirehtob neve ton
.erom flesmih rof pu dnats ot ,dlob eb ot mih gnillet syawla saw ehS
ffo deraelc d’eh ksed eht ot derutseg eH
.gnihcnum tpek dna
.daeh reh revo no ti gnidils ,trihs wen a tuo dellup dna gab reh koot retto ehT
dezzub enohp siH
,moor eht dnuora dekool tnecniV
.saw yllaer eh ylenol woh yb
.rehtnap emit-lluf dna ,retirw emit-trap a s’ohw
.mih dnuora elbatrofmoc tlef ylraelc ehS
.eergasid ylefas t’ndluoc eh raelc mih edam
,ylsuorogiv ruf sih hguorht ti nar dna lewot eht debbarg eH
,tleB dioretsA eht ,hcraM lairepmI ehT
”.ot esohc uoy sdeen s’enoyna ot dnet dluoc uoy teb I ,sediseB“
,ruf sih hguorht dekaos retaw ehT
”.em rof stnap ruoy evomer lliw uoY“
.epahs doog ni flesmih peek ot troffe detrecnoc a edam eh tub ,sllub htiw lacipyt sa
.pal sih no tas dna pirts did ehs
.niaga ffo gnittes erofeb dellac ehs
?haey ,llew pit dna yb sdneirf ruoy gnirB
,ssendnik A .erom gnihtoN
,elihw a rof retaw eht ni lever flesmih tel tsuj ot detpo evah thgim eh ,yrruh a ni t’nsaw eh fi dna ,mih dehtoos tI
”.ssadab a tahW .resopmoc cinoci tsom eht ylbaborp si smailliW nhoJ“
,eciov ylbbub eht deppihc ”,gniht eruS“  ”.azzip
.tseb eht ylisae s’tI“
.gnorts saw sreh no pirg siH
.xob eht ot detniop eH
mih fo llems detartnecnoc eht—
.mih tsniaga reh dloh ot detnaw llub eht
.laem reh morf reh tcartsid ti gnittel ton
delggig ehS .deksa eh
.tuo eugnot reh kcuts dna derekcins ehS
.mih ta ti gnissot dna azzip reh morf egasuas fo eceip a ffo gnikculp
,ybigreK yb ”sknahT gniviG“ saw sihT
,hguoht llitS .noitatrilf ton
.moorhtab eht ot ffo tnew dna ,lewot sih htiw enohp sih debbarg eh ,hguoht erusaem doog roF
.ekil t’ndid llub eht taht noitanibmoc taht tuoba gnihtyna t’nsaw erehT
dereviled yeht tub ,erus yleritne t’nsaw eH ?yhW
,deremmats eH ”!sdeen lanoitome reH
.reh fo snoitasnes eht ni ksab dna sih no ydob reh yojne
.yrd ssel ro erom mih gnivael dna
.gab regnessem reh morf retiL-2 eht dehctef dna denethgiarts ehs litnu
,noititeper eht yb detaesuan saw niarb s’tnecniV taht
”.won thgir ereh desucof noitnetta eht tnaw I kniht I“
”?eslup a evah I oD“
.kcolc sih ta dekool llub ehT
,sexob eht debbarg eH
.evag ydob ’srehto eht taht slangis eht llet ot elba ylraelc meht fo eno hcae
,epahs a ees ylerab tsuj dluoc eH
,mih ta dekool retto ehT
.awoI ni esruoc eht rof rap saw ylniatrec tI
.repmah yrdnual sih otni dessot ylsuoinomerecnu dna ylkciuq eh ,sehtolc siH
dellac ehs nehw spets eht nwod gniklaw saw dna llewriats eht ot rood eht denepo ydaerla dah ehS
”.won yb ti fo derit er’uoy enigami I ,hguohT
.od ot saw taht gniht a diputs woh dezilaer neht dna ,deddon eH
,dewollaws tnecniV
.uoy ot riaf t’nsaw gnitaehc tub ,haeY“
,deudbus erom saw moor sih ot kcab klaw ehT
.ti fo gnihtyna kniht t’ndid tnecniV
.daeh reh deddon ehS
;placs sih ot nroh sih nwod dnah reh nar yraM
”.ereht m’I nehw kcab rebmun siht llac ll’I
,hcamots reh gnola sessik fo sliart tfos dessik eh dna
.mih ta pu dekool dna deppots ehS
.dab ylirassecen s’taht kniht t’nod I“
?ti kcolnu ehs did woh tuB
.mih ni detseretni saw ehs yaw on saw erehT
.reh tuoba tsrif deciton dah eh taht eciov ylevil tub
.woh gninoitseuq saw eh fi sa tsomla ,dias eh
,tfos taht ni deooc ehs
.won etanoissap erom saw ssik riehT
,elims taht erofeB
”?gnivigsknahT no gnikrow uoy era yhW ?uoy tuoba tahW
.pu meht deyalp eh dna
,dias retto eht ”,yeH“
.moc.yrrufos.ybigrek//:sptth