si yrots s’yadot dna
”?erofeb tbed htiw melborp a dah uoy evaH“
”.reverof yawa og dna ksa uoy sa od llahs I ,trac ym xif uoy fI .laeD“
”,ytsriht gnileef era uoy fi retaw emos uoy teg nac I“
.elihw a rof pohc mih tel I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”,lufrewop eb nac ti
,ograc sih raen gnieb enoemos diova ot hsiw ot mih rof nosaer saw ereht fi neve oS
”,em tuoba gnihtemos tuo derugif evah uoy os ,hA“
.remmah sih dnif ot liaf ot deunitnoc eh sa dias I
”.dnammoc ruoy rednu gnieb ni tseretni on evah I
.gnihtemos rof gnikool
,negramxirF .R.W yb
.niaga xob eht desolc neht dna ,ti edisni dnuora delffuhs ,sexob eht fo eno rehtona denepo ,trac sih ta nwod decnalg eH
”.eil a si ssendniK
.hgual ot nageb neht dna detrons eH
.raelc saw erutseg eht
ylwols emac sdrow siH
.llih eht nwod gnimoc em dettops eh nehw ylthgils pmuj ot demees eh ,llitS
”,nwo rieht no ffo klaw tsuj t’nod sremmaH“
seye sih ni llet dluoc I tub ,nwod tas dah I ecnis hcrep ym morf devom ton dah I
.dnuora liat ym lruc dna nopu tis ot
,laeh ot trats ebyam ot ksir a ekat oT
tas I erehw dnuora htap ediw a koot eH
”.tser a esu dluoc yeht ekil smees tsael yrev eht ta rO
.ecnatsid sih gnipeek llitS
trac eht dniheb devom dna
.em htiw gnilaed fo daetsni remmah a sa krow dluow taht gnihtemos ekam tsuj dluoc eh fi gnirednow tbuod oN
mih erofeb gol eht morf ezag sih dellup eH
.ylreporp em ees dluoc eh os hguone tsuj ylno tuB
”,flesym siht fo erac ekat ll’I
.elkcuhc a htiw deksa I
.sraey ot shtnom ot syad emos rof uoy evres rO
”?nosrep ym no ti ees uoy oD“
,trac eht fo edis raf eht no saw eh nevig em hsur yllaer t’ndluoc eh hguohT
dna sexob htiw nedal saw trac ehT
.aera eht dnuora neht dna ,esuoh ym ot pu neht ,em ta dekool eH
.uoy ekil sodriew yllaicepsE
flesmih raen em gnittel tuoba deirrow mih kniht ot elbanosaer sa tsuj saw ti
”traC eht dna navrolG“
.niaga truh eb ot tnaw t’nod uoy dnA
pleh fo deen ni esoht peek lliw ksa yeht ecirp hgih eht
”?t’naC“   ”.t’nac I ,llew
”.sregnarts morf pleh gnikat ekil t’nod I
.em ta dekool dna
troffe fo tol a htiw tuB .llud egde eht dna edurc saw latem ehT
fo etamitse na gnikam erofeb sehcnarb rewol eht gnivomer krow ot tog eH
.noitcafsitas laem tsop fo wolg tnasaelp eht ni gniregnil saw I sa emoh ym edistuo no sgniog eht ni detseretni ylralucitrap neeb t’ndah I
”,pleh fo sreffo rieht rof tnemyap sdnamed enoyreve ton taht nrael uoy litnu reverof yawa og ylno ,hA“
kcab delbmuts kcub ehT
”.era htob ew ebyam neht ,nialpxe t’nac uoy fi esuaceB“ .kcab derewsna I
,I ,taht tsuj si tI“
elxa wen a sa elbatius eb thgim taht ,knurt thgiarts a ylraen htiw dna ,gnuoy ,trohs a
.egamad suoivbo eht si trac ruoY
.htap eht gnola enots fo tib ralucitrap a dna ograc yvaeh fo noitanibmoc eht saw
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”?uoy erA“   .em deksa eh
.ti deppord dah eh erehw dessap eh sa trihs sih gnibbarg
”?hcum woH“ ,dias dna
tiolpxe taht esoht ylno taht dnA
.ezag ym ni mih peek ot nrut ton did dna ,em dnuora klaw mih tel I
”?doow emos ekat I fi stnialpmoc ynA“
.leef rO .kniht mih tel I
.ytisoiruc fo noitseuq a rewsna ot tneced si ti sulP
”,flesym trac ym fo erac ekat nac I“   .dias I
.netsil ot ydaer m’I
?sregnarts ton era ohw tub wonk uoy elpoeP“
”.esiwrehto evorp dluow ohw esoht morf yawa uoy eracs ot yrt lliw dnA
.deddon I   ”.esoht fo enoN“
.ygolopa na em dewo eh tlef neve eH
”.thgin hcae emoh kcab remmah nwo ym erul ot yaw a tuo erugif ot deen d’I eslE“ .dias I ”,ton epoh d’I“   .tuo detniop eh
,hcrep ym dnuora ediw gniog niaga ,trac eht sdrawot kcab ti deggard eh sA
,trac eht ot yaw eht lla hcaer ot hguone gnol ylraen ton tub ,yhtgnel saw tI
.eil a si ssendnik taht uoy llet ll’yeht
.htap eht ffo tsuj kcor a nehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mih ot revo dellac I
.tuoba yrrow uoy rotcelloc tbed a t’nsi ti spahreP
detneserp flesym dnuof dna emoh ym tfel I ,romalc eht fo esuac eht ot sa suoiruC
”.dlrow regral eht morf detalosi uoy peek ot eunitnoc ti tel ot ro
.enot yrotasucca na ni dias eh
”?remmah ym tup uoy did erehW“
.dias eh ”,egnarts yrev era uoY“
”.sdneirf wen gnikam ni detseretnisid mees tey dna ,sregnarts morf pleh tpecca t’nod uoy yas uoY“
.smsirennam dna tnetni ym ni
.gnikcarc doow fo dnuos eht yb gninrom eno debrutsid saw I
”.yrt ot gnilliw eb dluow I tuB“ .dias I
,rehto eht fo raeF
.trac eht yb gol eht deppord eh sa dias eh
”,erutuf eht ni uoy pleh ot em tnaw ll’uoy
dnaH a flesruoY eviG ni
”?uoy llet I dluohs yhW“
.trihs sih ffo llup dna htaerb sih hctac ot esuap a koot eh
,nwod ti denrut I tuB
.revo gnillaf saw ti dna retal skcahw doog erom wef A
”,deen ni eb ot raeppa uoy dnA
,sdoow eht morf raf ton devil I taht gniwonK
.tnelis saw kcub ehT
,gnippohc sih gnisuap toN
.xob denepo eht ni kcab tehctah eht tup mih dehctaw I
lufecaep kool ot tseb ym did I
.daeh sih detfil eH
”,pleh emos deen thgim uoy derugif dna sukcur a draeh I“
.gnola gnillup neeb dah kcub eht trac eht fo elxa tnorf eht kaerb ot deripsnoc ylraelc dah noitanibmoc ehT
,trac ruoy xif I fI“ .detrats I
gniyap ni detseretni ton m’I dnA“
.kcub yraet eht dlot I
.daeh sih derewol eH
.dias I ”,suoires m’I“
”,tbed s’enoyna ni eb ot tnaw t’nod uoy oS“
,bmuht rieht rednu uoy peek ot kees ohw esoht os dnA
,snoitacilbuP laoG yb
,negramxirF .R.W yb
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.ediced ot enim ton saw koot eh htap hcihW
.deremmats eh ”,tsuj si tI“
.lla ta looc peek mih gnipleh t’nsaw robal sih dna ,yad mraw a saw tI
.trac sih gnixif no krow mih tel ot detpo I ,daetsnI
.llih eht dnuora tib a saw
taht ezilaer uoy sa emit hcus litnu niaga ereh nruter reven ot deen uoy
.retal skeew eerht niaga kcub eht was I
.sreltna htiw wollef gnikool etari yrev a ti ot txen dah dna detlit dekool trac ehT .trac a saw
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy
.trac eht ni sexob eht fo eno rof dehcaer eh ,tuo mih tiaw ot gniog saw I taht was eh ecnO   .ylsuoiruc
snoitnetni ym tuoba tbuod ruoy evomer oT ?pleh ym rof ecirp a uoy evig I tuoba woh
.spih sih no sdnah sih tup kcub ehT
.enif eb dluohs I“
.em ot seye sih desiar dna
”.sdneirf wen deen t’nod I“ ,derewsna eh
hcnarB kaO etorw ohw dna
.gnihcraes sih ot nruter ot trac sih ot kcab tnew dna deffuh eH
.ti od ot detcelloc dah eh gol eht deen t’ndid I taht tnemal did I hguohT
.ecalp ym yb nar taht
”?noitasrevnoc ekam oT“
,og lanif eht rof ydaer tuoba dekool eh erofeb gnol toN
.roiretni eht morf loot a tfil dna xob a nepo enola tel
.kool deyonna na em tohs eh sa detnap eH
”,pleh tuohtiw xif ot emit emos ekat thgim tahT ?erus uoY“ .elxa
.elpoep ot tbed ni gnieb ekil t’nod I“ .dias eh
.dnatsrednu I ,ton fi tuB
,dias dna ,ecnayonna sih detrons
”,snoitnetni ym dnatsrednusim uoy kniht I ?tnemyaP ?dnammoC“
.eert dellef eht morf deen t’ndluow eh tahw fo tsal eht ffo gnikaerb
.detcepxenu oot t’nsaw em dessot kcub eht noitseuq eht os dnA
,eert tseraen ehT
”,taht lla hguorht uoy pleh ot eno eht erus rof m’I fi wonk t’nod I“
.ti fo emit hguot a gnivah saw eh nehw
ecalp tcefrep ehT
.pmuts eht elcric ot nageb kcub ehT
.em truh ot gniyrt ereht tuo enoemos
”?ti si erehw ,ylsuoireS“
.macs rieht morf yawa
htap ediw taht dnuora elcric mih tel I daetsnI
,ti tuoba klat ot ekil d’uoy fI“
”.yas ot drah era sgniht emoS
.niaga ecno pu ti dliub rO .noisnet sih esae rO
.sriaper sih nigeb ot eert fo tros thgir eht llef dluoc eh
.pleh ot tnaw tub pleh t’nac dna
”.em wonk ot teg ot esoohc os uoy fi em tuoba erom hcu   m wonk uoy tel ot yppah ma I“
.pleh deen yeht ekil skool ohw enoemos era uoy esuaceb pleh nac I fi ees ot hsiw I“ .denialpxe I
”.ta teg nac yeht enoyna rO
.eert eht dehcaorppa dna
.em no kcab sih nrut reven ot regae etiuq demees eh tuB .krow ot tog dna tehctah eht detfil kcub ehT .dias eh
.gol eht debbarg dna nwod dehcaer eH
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?uoy truh ot gniog m’I woh tsuj ,raelc yllatot
.pmuts nesohc ym fo weiv ni hcum yrev llits tuB
htap eht no dnA
.tserof eht deraef ohw esoht yb hguone netfo tuoba draeh tbuod on dah eh taht
.deecorp ot woh esoohc ot dah ohw kcub eht saw tI
,dlrow eht ni elpoep doog era ereht
”,enif eb dluohs eno tahT“
,sgniws doog erom elpuoc a gnikat erofeb tuo dellac eh ”,si ti erehT“
,ngineb tsom eht ta nevE“
.devresbo dah flesmih eh taht hturt taht tuoba stbuod sih dah eh taht
.uoy tsniaga noitaler ruoy desu ohw rebmem ylimaf a rO
.esoht fo eno sa em ees uoy os dnA
.renwo trac eht dehcaorppa yllausac I os
”?em gnirehtob uoy era yhW
”,esoht fo enoN“   .tuo hsal ot ro ,niap diova ot
.seye sih morf sraet eht epiw ot gniyrt dias eh ”,llew ,I“
.em etaulave ot emit sih koot eh sa
”?em gnihctaw uoy era yhW“
.derewol llits erew sreltna esohT
.detcelloc dah eh gol eht seye kcub ehT   ”?laeD
.elims a htiw dias I
.taht ekil si ti sseug I“
ssendnik esuba dluow ohw esoht rof lufesu si tI“ .dias I ”,yldraH“
”.trac ym xif ot uoy rof
,ssertsid ni enoemos ees I taht si laed yM“
diarfa elpoep peek oT
.ekam ot noisiced doog a ton saw derugif I ,tnemom taht ta taht tuoba pu gnikaeps tuB
.elbissop sa rehto hcae morf raf sa dnik era ohw esoht peek ot
htap eht ot llih eht nwod weiv a htiw
.trac sih dexif I os dnA
.enif si taht dnA .wonk ton dluohs I
”,remmah ruoy dehcuot ton evah I“
.delbmurg eh ”,eniF“   .desserp I
tuo mih pleh ot elba eb ot lufetarg tsuj saw I taht mih gnillet
.hgih pu smra ym gnittup elihw ria eht ni pu sgel ym detfil dna kcab denael I   .desserp eh
.em ta pu dekool neht eH
.uoy fo gnihtemos dnamed lliw ohw enoemoS
,sesuac esoht tnorfnoc ot dna
.detatiga ylbisiv erom werg eh sa dnuora noissessop sih gnimmals ,derewsna eh
.trac eht ni sexob eht ta nwod gnikool erofeb detsisni eh
seirots erom roF
yawa deirrucs eh sa deddon I
”,emoh teg ot deen I .nwod yal ot deen t’nod I“
tnorf eht fo tfel saw tahw ees ot hguone esolC .trac eht morf raf ton desuap dah I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”,siht si ecirp yM“
.yltsenoh derewsna I
.deen ni esoht pleh ot thgir si ti esuaceB“   .deksa eh
.ssergorp saw ereht tuB .wols yllufniap saw ssergorp siH
”,yas dluow gnihtemos stnaw ohw enoemos gnihtemos ekil tsuj ,smees tahT“
.daeh sih koohs kcub ehT   .derewsna I
.rewsna sih evag eh
.t’nac tsuj I .revE
.trac sih fo stnetnoc eht fo esuaceb pleh ym tnaw t’ndid eh taht emussa ot ysae eb dluow ti woN
.worran seye sih dna dekrep erew srae siH
dediced evah uoy sa ,wonk t’nod I
”,neht siht tuoba woh ,eniF“   .kcab detnurg eh
”?tnaw uoy od tahW“
.egap ytiniffaruF sih no
,etelpmoc saw krow eht dezilaer eh retfA
”.tbed rieht ni elpoep peek ot ekil ohw
?siht si esnesnon tahW“ .tuo detnurg eh
”,sregnarts morf pleh ekat t’nod I ,dias I sA“
.pmuts eht morf pu gnisir dias I
.uoy truh sah enoemos taht raelc si ti tuB
xob pot eht fo dil eht demmals eH
.sgniht ym rO .tnemyap ni trac ym revo dnah I dnamed neht dna tuo em pleh uoy ,tsrow tA
.rof gnikool saw eh loot txen eht dnif ot deliaf llits dna ,rehtona denepo dna xob taht desolc eH
.truh gnieb ksir t’nac I“   .desserp I
noitagilbo tuohtiw ylgnilliw erahs ot dna reffo ot
raef taht dne ot tnaw uoy fi
,secirp nwonknu fo esuaceb ssendnik on tpecca dluow uoy fI“
.uoy deyarteb ohw dneirf a tuB
.eert llams eht ta gniws rehtona koot dna detnurg kcub ehT   .detroter I
.sruoy fo tehctah roop taht htiw ti llef ot emit emos uoy ekat thgim ti hguohT“ .derewsna I
”.sregnarts gnieb pots nac ew spahrep
.tsetorp ym deciov I erofeb gnippohc trats ot mih rof gnitiaw saw I fi gnirednow spahrep ,deksa eh
drawrof tneb dna nwod kcab sbmil ym tup I .deksa I
,pleh sreffo ohw enoyreve dnA“
.hgis detarepsaxe na tuo tel ot nrut ym saw tI
”?toidi ro loof fo tros emos uoy erA“
.ereht gnidnats tsuj fo setunim ynam retfa dias eh
,yrruh a ni yawa ti hsup ot nageb dna trac eht debbarg yltnelis eh
.doowerif sa retal ti fo esu doog edam llits I tuB
”,dnatsrednu I kniht I“ .deddon I   ”.revE .ti ksir t’nac tsuj I …dna suoivbo ton gnihtemos ro ,suoivbo gnihtemoS .gnihtemos tnaw yeht ,yeht
su fo emos era ereht tahT
.seitic ni devil dna sdleif eht dekrow ohw esoht ot elitsoh sgniht dna elpoep fo stros lla htiw dellif erew neht kcab emoh ym raen sdoow eht taht uoy dnimer dluohs I tuB
.tnasaelpnu taht ylraen ton saw tserof eht wenk esruoc fo I
.kcab evig ot thguoht reven ohw revol a rO
mih gnihctaw trats ot
.erom ecno thgis ym ot nruter dna
,raelc ti ekam dna
seert eht fo swodahs eht ni krul taht serutaerc gnipeerc ro sdrol doolb ro stidnab eht fo eno neeb ylisae evah dluoc I sa
syawla s’ereht esuaceB
,ffo tib riaf a saw kcub ehT
sruf ydeerg dna evitalupinam fo sllaftip eht gnidiova ni sretniop emos reffo dluoc I spahrep
.spahreP“   .tuo detniop eh
”.worrob uoy tel ot yppah eb d’I taht emoh ym ni eno evah I hguohT“
.uoy tiolpxe dluow ohw esoht fo lluf dlrow a ni evil uoy leef uoY“
tlit trac eht fo esuac eht taht ylisae desseug I
syaw emos ni uoy ekam oT
”,elbuort emos dah evah ot raeppa uoY“
.shtaerb peed wef a retfa dedda eh
.doog od ot tnaw yllautca ohw
,flesym rennam a hcus ni nedloheb gnieb sekilsid ohw enoemos sa dnA
.tehctah a detcartxe dna ti denepo eH
enoyreve ton dna
.ylraelc meht ecnuonorp ot gnilggurts saw eh sa
.noitcerid lareneg ym ni sreltna sih gnirewol neve saw eh ylevitcnitsnI
”?spahrep secnatniauqcA“
”traC eht dna navrolG“:yojne esaelP
,em ta kcab dekool neht kcub ehT
dna edur eb dluow edisni gninruter dediced I
,noigel eb nac raef taht fo sesuac ehT“ .dias I
,sregnarts morf ytirahc gnikat ekil t’nod uoy fI …wonk uoy dnA“
”?ecnatsissa yna deen uoy oD“ .mih dlot I
.hguone eb t’now ,hcus ni tseretni on evah I gniyas em dnA .evals ym
,stros suoirav fo ssendam dna if-ics snwaps ohw
?laed ruoy si tahW
”traC eht dna navrolG“ saw sihT
.pleh uoy reffo reve
”,ecirp a htiw semoc syawla pleH“
pmuts a flesym dnif t’ndid I naem t’ndid taht tuB
negramxirF .R.W yb
.llew sa ees ot mih rof liat ym pu tfil ot
”.uoy ot meht dnel ot yppah eb dluow I
dehgis eh yllaniF
.skeehc sih no sraet eht ylraelc ees dluoc I ,desiar won sreltna esoht htiw tub
?noitasrevnoc ekam oT“
,taht dna yaw siht daeh sih denarc neht eH
ediced ot uoy ot pu si ti dnA
”.nialpxE“ .desop I ”?ecirP“
ffo yawa raf ton
”?deen ni era uoy fi tuo uoy pleh lliw ohw enoemos fo ssenerawA
.emoh ym ot denruter neht dna
,on ,oN“   ”…htiw pleh nac I
”,gninaem m’I tahw ton s’taht tuB
snaem ti esuaceb
.ralugnis eb nac yeht ro
.emoh ym ni sloot emos evah I“ .tuo detniop I
.emit a rof kaeps ro evom ton did tuB
.uoy mrah ot stnaw
.pot eht ffo pohc dluohs eh erehw
.edutitta dedraug dna smsirennam sih nevig noitpmussa ysae nA
”.dnik si ohw enoemos teem ot ecnahc eht dah reven spahrep ev’uoy esuaceB