.em tsniaga thgit si ti
eeffochtiwflow@ ta
.enola etiR eht htiw hguorht og sinaS tel t’nac I tub ,ysereh si sihT
,evitanretla retteb a sa suhccaB fo tseirp hgih eht ot uoy tseggus nac I ,nigriv a sA
.ffo skaerb eh nehw syas eh ”,pu tuhS“
,esool semoc sinaS ,pop a dna niap fo hsalf a htiW
.nwod em gninnip ,neht em nopu s’eh dna yawa llor I
.esir ot su wolla dna
piy dna lworg I dna
.lautir eht yfsitas ot hguone nigriv si
.sgel ym neewteb morf sdrawkcab spils eH ,gnirats
.noitasrevnoc ruo raeh dluoc eh wonk I dna
”.etiR eht morf em esaeler dog ym taht ksa dna
.esac sti otni kcab ti pils dna
.eniw fo dog eht ,suhccaB ot etir dercas lataf a mrofrep ot deerga ylsuoiverp dah sinaS dneirf sih tuo dnuof
.thgin eht rof deriter gnivah srehtorb eht fo tsom
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
.thginot suhccaB fo tseirp hgih eht ot kaeps em teL .llew yreV“
,uoy nioj ot dedeen I
.dnuorg eht sehcuot elzzum sih taht os wol swob dna
.efil txen ym ni mih evres ot eunitnoc nac I nehw yad eht ot drawrof kool dna
raj eht otni regnif a spid eH
,tnemom a rof dniheb sniamer tsireM .retlehs rof nur
,mrof dedooh sih gnihctaw woN
,ratla eht hcaorppa I sA
,kcen ym fo ffurcs eht yb em spirg ylhguor eh erofeb flesmih gnikorts dna wap sih gninetsiom mih raeh nac I
tpo ylgnilliw ot setaitini rof nevig si ecnahc ehT“
”,dnatsrednu t’nod I“
.em sbarg cennef ehT
,ynitsed ym fo trap si mih htiw gnieb taht
mih ot kcab elcric I
”,nigriv a ton ma I“
.em morf yawa sllup cennef ehT
mih nioj htob lliw uoy
.stseirp eht gnoma repsihw a si erehT .yas I
etamitni os si noitca ehT
”sdoG eht fo yrolG“
.su no kcab sih gninrut ,setaitini eht ot syas eh ”,meht lliK“
.ecnad eht otni evah I gnihtyreve tup evah I tub
.dnuos ot nigeb smurd eht sa snoitisop enorp ruo morf pu teg htob eW
?neeb I evah diputs woH .naorg dna
”,noitcetorp reh rednu esoht mialc uoy fi tespu eb lliw anaiD tub ,ton od I deednI“
,su dnuora swolb dniw ehT
.si siht drawkwa woh leef llits I tub
.sleenk dna tseirp eht ot snrut dna
dnoces eht eht saw sihT
”tsireM ,em ot dneirf doog a neeb evah uoY“
,won rehtegot er’ew tsael tA
lio evilo yna evah t’nseod eh ezilaer I
,dog eht ot ytinigriv ruoy reffo ot dehsiw uoy em dlot tsireM nehW“ ”.si tI“
spih sih gnitfihs
gnilliw neeb dah I ylno fI
,dnuora sklaw eH .llaf srae yM
.enots eht otno dees ym gnillips ,xamilc I dna egde eht revo em sekat
.em ssim dluow eh em llet ot deppots dah eh
,em morf yrautcnas eht ssorca sdnats sinaS
.etaitini nigriv detceles ylsuoiverp eht fo ecalp ni etir eht mrofrep uoy tel llahs I“
.tnemom a rof sredisnoc eH
.meht ees ot elba neeb ylno dah I fi
.gnola em sllup dna
.etsaw ton dluohs ew
.degnarra eb dluoc tahT“
.separg gnidloh enots ni ylduorp sdnats ,mrof taog sih ni ,suhccaB
,gnileef eht ot desu teg I dna gnisnet spots ydob ym ecnO
.daeh sih revo enim ekil dooh yvaeh a
.tuo kcab flesmih llup ot skrow eh
,taeH ni deraeppa sah krow s’eyEthgiN
.em ta sreel flow eht
,troffe fo tib a sekat tI
,mih rednu lworg I
sevom eseht taeper eW .ffo gnikcab dna
skool cennef ehT .kcab repsihw I
,desaelp neeb evah ot degduj si suhccaB fI
,dog eht fo eman eht ni decnad evah uoY“
,thginot dog ruo desaelp evah uoY“ .ti psarg I
.eugnot sih fo skcil eltneg
,tseirp hgih ehT
dael sih wollof I
.yrarbil eht sdrawot kcab sdaeh eh nehT
”.llew sa ydaer ma I“
.etaitini nigriv a dna
,emit lanif eno sgnirps eht tisiv ot tuo tes dah eh erofeb ,yadoT
,su evoba tub ,ria eht hguorht gniylf era sevael dna
”.htuos eht morf lacarac si ehS .ailliV“ .gnidaer sih morf pu skool eH
.neehs thgil a htiw yawa semoc dna
”.ereh yas on evah uoY“
.emoctuo eht tceffa nac uoy ebyam tub
.wap ’sinaS leef I dna dnah thgir ym htiw tuo hcaer I
tsuj I ,em rof derac eh wonk t’ndid I taht t’nsaw tI
.su nopu nwod gnikool
.yks eht ta slwocs dna etunim a rof pu serats eH .pu skool neht
.tnemegdelwonkca ni daeh ym bob I
.edisniatnuom eht ssorca gnippihw dniw eht
,did tsuj ew noitom ralucric eht taeper neht ew dna ydob dna
.etaf ruo segnahc noitnevretni ym taht epoh ylno nac I
,em ta gnikool syas sinaS ”!naksA“
.kcoc ym ta gnilkcus si eh dna
enola mih tfel I
”?siht rof elpoep ecifircas yeht tsum yhW“ .hgis I
,yawa skcab dna em steem eh dna
”.ratla eht ot meht gnirB“
,su ta skool tseirp ehT .syas eh
.sksa eh ”?siht hsiw uoy dluow yhW“ .em ot revo sklaw dna pu steg tseirp ehT
”.dnatsrednu I ,sinaS rof enip uoY“
.edis eno no ratla enots a htiw aera nepo talf egral a si tI
”?noob siht tpecca uoy oD
.xof der dlo eht ot yas I
.kcab dooh ym pilf dna pu hcaer I
,noisiced eht detpecca sah suhccaB neve taht smees tI
,elttil a selims eH .sksa tseirp ehT
eeffoc rof tnahcnep a evah ot deromur si ohw rekamelbuort nwonk a
# ”.mih hcaorppa dluohs uoy ,worromoT
.repsihw I ”,seY“ .wollaws I
,neht ycnetop rieht fo emos esol stsurht siH
.em ediug modsiw tel ot
efil ni esoprup sih dnif yllanif ot redro ni
,evah srehtorb eht sdrocer eht ni dna
,tsrif ta em htiw eltneg si sinaS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
,mih fo pot no ma
”.taht fo semoc revetahw dna ,eniw eht
naksA tsinogatorp ruo ,emit tsaL
,tsaef eht ot og flesruoy tel tsum uoY
”.rehtegot evil nac eW
seye ym nepo I yllaniF
.neddus oot ,driew oot si sihT
.edis niatnuom eht dnuora ohce smurd ehT
yawa pets setaitini eht sa
,levoh elttil ruo ni kcab era ew eveileb nac I ,tnemom a roF
,ebor eht evomer stnadnetta eht dna smra ym pu dloh I ”?woH
I wonk I gniht txeN
.detcepxe si tahw tuoba
,redrah em otni flesmih gnisserp mih leef nac I ;hguor s’tI
,sniatnuom eht fo edis rehto eht no ,yellav eht ssorcA
.tey ma I ohw dezilaer t’nsah eh ,lautir eht no desucof os si eh ezilaer I
”.ekat ot gnilliw ma I ksir a s’tI“
em sdrawot secnalg sinaS
,gnineppah morf ti pots t’nac uoY“
,mih ta gnikool diova ot seye ym esolc I
thgiew sih stfihs neht eH
.tseirp hgih eht slworg
detfil em evoba thgiew eht leef I
ylivaeh niar ot snigeb tI .ylgnigdurg fi
.ydob sih fo tuo og noisnet eht dna
.suhccaB ot yllohw sevlesmeht egdelp ylgnilliw ohw esoht yb demrofrep ylno si etiR ehT“
fo trap lanif dna
sdnah ym ni daeh ym tup I
,noitanimreted wols a htiw dna dexamilc ev’I wonk mih stel ydob ym fo gnikauq ehT
nemow dna nem htob rof snoitcurtsni deliated era ereht dna ,rettam ton seod srecnad eht fo xes ehT
.em tsniaga pu flesmih snoitisop eh sa
.war em ekat ot evah lliw dna
.etarapes niaga ew erofeb ,tnemom a rof redluohs ym no elzzum sih syal eh tub
.ti htaenrednu htaerb toh sih dna liat ym tfil mih leef I esuaceb ,em fo daeha fo pets eno si sinaS ,esruoc fO
ratla eht nopu sllaf thgilnoom fo yar elgnis A
.detaba sah rednuht dna gninthgil eht tub
,neht pu dekohc ylraen dah I
”?sinaS htiw lautir eht mrofrep ot si ohw wonk uoy od ,tsireM“
ffo sklaw dna lassimsid ni dnah sih sevaw eh ,yllaniF
.nepo gnignah ,ebor esool a sraew eH
.suhccaB ot flesruoy reffo uoy taht gnittif si tI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.eniw eht fo lufhtuom egral a wollaws I
.efil txen ruoy ni mih evres ot no tnes eb htob lliw uoy
suhccaB fo etaitini decneirepxe na yb demrofrep si etir ehT
”?dnim ni evah uoy od tahW
lautir eht fo gninnigeb eht ta eniw fo ecilahc a erahs lliw yehT
.ecilahc egral a gniyrrac
suhccaB fo etaitini doog A“
,em ot klat t’now sinaS ecnis dna ,etiR eht tuoba nac I gnihtyreve nrael ot deen I
.lwob llams a pu skcip dna
lio evilo erom ni regnif sih spid eH
.enots eht ssorca trovac ew dna
.stuohs dna sdnah sih pu stfil suhccaB fo tseirp hgih ehT
.deiduts evah I“ mih ta elims I
,sduolc eht dniheb kcab spid noom ehT
”.rehtegot yrotsih …ruoy nevig
noob a su nevig evah sdog eht dna
”?retteb hcum wonk uoy enoemos
”!siht od ot ydaer ton era uoY
.siad eht raen srehto ot snoitom eH
hctac htaerb sih leef I
”.anaiD revo mih evres ot nesohc evah uoy desaelp eb lliw suhccaB
.em dloh nac eh os ,em dniheb semoc cennef eht emit sihT
,efil nwo ruoy pu evig ot uoy gniksa doohrehtorB eht morf tnereffid taht lla yllaer ti sI
.seigolohtna rehto dna gnaF
,rehto hcae hcaorppa txen ew nehW
.su ta gnivaw dna gnilims erofeb
,yhtrow owt eseht dnif uoy fI
.tluc eht yb desu
.seye ym esolc I
.seye ym rednu ruf eht stniona dna
.em tsniaga yltneg sesserp eH
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
.yellav eht ot htuos eht morf mirglip devirra yltnecer a em
gnittis saw eh erehw ot revo sklaw eH
.nwod eciov sih peek ot gniyrt
em sehcaorppa eh nehw mih gniteem
.mih ot tnemtimmoc ym dnatsrednu noos lliw eh wonk I
.redro ruo fo setiR tneicna tsom eht fo eno mrofrep llahs uoy rehtegoT !setaitinI“
.pu gnitniop syas eh
,elcric ediw a ni em dnuora peews ot snigeb neht dna
.tseirp hgih eht syas ”,supmylO ta mih evres ot uoy rof sehsiw eh dna
.gniwerb si mrots a dna ,krad si tI
sah eH .sinaS dlot ton evah I tub
.dekcohs skool eh dna
.em ot txen dial sinaS htiw ,enots eht no tuo em yal yehT
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna eseht piks nac uoy
.ecap rewols a semuser eh sa yltfos srepsihw eh ”,yrroS“
.em morf kcab gnippets
”.sinaS gnikat morf sdog eht peek dluow taht fi flesym ecalp s’ailliV ekat d’I …wonk t’nod I“
.suhccaB ot flesym evig ot deen I
.yltfos dnal I erus ekam ot em sehctac eh dna
,nesohc era srecnad htob yllausU
.em fo tnorf ni lautir eht gnibircsed llorcs a evah I
elihw nwod em sdloh etaitini enO
ecifircas eht timrep ot gnilliw regnol on ma I tuB
,deriuqer animats eht evah uoY“ .em gnisiarppa
.egap eht revo wap ym ecart I
,sinaS htiw ecnad ruoy fo sevorppa suhccaB fI
”,desaelp si suhccaB“
.tsireM ot revo klaw dna yawa llorcs eht tup I
drah em spirg eH
ecilahc eht sekat dna
,ereht erew sngis ehT
.mih drawot denrut evah uoy taht desaelp eb lliw eH
!naksA ,evil nac eW“
mhtyhr a semoceb gnimmurd ehT
.edisni llits ,em tsniaga kcab sgas eH
!taht wonk t’nod yehT !hhS“ .dnah a pu sdloh eH “-a ton m’I“ .tib a tegdif I
.reggad a secudorp rehtona
.sinaS rof si siht
.ylwols ni flesmih sesserp eH
,snoitom sih htiw kciuq si cennef ehT
”?lakcaj siht rof sdog eht fo htarw eht rucni dluow uoY“
tfos htiw em mir ot strats eh sa tnemom a rof pu kcol ydob elohw ym leef I
gnihtemos yas ot tnaw I
.pu sevlesmeht evig ot sah
sevlesmeht sdog eht fo htarw eht ksir ot deen lliw lakcaj eht
.efil txen eht ni yltcerid suhccaB evres ot
.elbisiv yllanif ecaf sih ,kcab dooh sih spilf sinaS ,gniknird hsinif I nehW
.wap ’sinaS ezeeuqs dna
.srumrum enoyrevE
,em otni eugnot sih sserp mih leef I sa sedaf tnemom ehT
”.reh htiw krow ot woh wonk ll’eH
.neht ,enola siht od ton lliw sinaS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.gniod er’ew tahw fo tuo em sllup ti
?nigeb neve nac I erofeb ecnelosni ym rof nwod em ekirts retipuJ evah suhccaB lliW .ecnatsid eht ni gninthgil fo sehsalf erom ees nac I
,su ta dam era sdog rehto eht fi nevE
.si eno tsuj semitemos tub
.desuma skool flow ehT
.siad eht fo tnorf ni ratla enots eht ot revo deirrac ma I
.em fo edisni peed dekcol s’eh sa
.srepsihw eh ”?ydaer uoy erA“
,gnirps eht yb emit sih fo tsom tneps
# ”.eb lliw uoy suhccaB fo etaitini na nehT“
.raelc si snevaeh eht morf ngis ehT
,ecnad eht htiw deecorp neht dna
.kcohs ni nezorf m’I
.kcab yal srae yM
.tseirp hgih eht ta pu kool dna
rehtegot decifircas eb lliw setaitini eht
”.ereh sinaS evael dna etips fo tuo uoy ekat thgim eh ,oslA
.stnuocca levart emos hguorht gnidaer pu llits si tsireM
won traeh ym ni wonk I
.tsurht sih htiw ti emit ot gniyrt
,wap ’sinaS ekat I
.ssenkrad otni degnulp neeb sah elpmet eht fo tser eht elihw era ew erehw
.su etarapes yllufecrof dna su hcaorppa setaitini deksaM
”.ereh eid lliw uoy ,naksA“
.su htiw sdnats llits anaiD
.eciov sih ni reens a htiw ,suhccaB fo tseirp hgih eht stuohs
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.nwod gniralg ,su evoba sdnats tseirp ehT
.ratla eht ta dereffo eb lliw riap eht
;ydob eht evah ylniatrec uoy dna
.ecnad siht ni evissimbus eht ma I dna
.ezeerb eht ni palf
,flesym ekorts I dna
.ecnad eht wonk t’nod uoY“
,reyarp tnelis ni snevaeh eht sdrawot pu denrut daeh sih
,mih fo gnileef ehT
.niatnuom eht fo edis eht otni tliub si elpmet ria nepo ehT
,gnikorts nwo ym htiw denibmoc
.won tes si htap yM
,su gnihctaw era elpoeP
.snoitazilivic tneicna ,daed ni tseretni na dna
.siad eht no gnitiaw si tseirp ehT
.emit si tI .flesym ydaets I
,wohs rof tsuj ,elggurts I
ytitsahc fo wov ruoy fo gnikaerb ehT
,suhccaB yb nesohc fI
.elpmet eht fo sedis eht dnuora gnidnats
.htrof dna kcab nips ew sa
.etiR eht mrofrep uoy tel ot em rof etairporppa saw ti fi rednow ot dah I
,uoy pots t’ndluoc I fi ,esuaceB“
.em ot resolc ni gnipeews syas eh ”,tsum I“ ”?woN“
.su gnitarapes no skrow eh elihw
.daeh sih sekahs xof ehT
.seye ym esolc I
.nihc ym hctarcs I
;egde eht revo mih sehsup siht ,tniop emos tA
.telbog eht em sdnah neht dna
”!skaeps anaiD fo tsactuo ehT“
sebor yvaeh no evah I
tsrif pu spets sinaS
.etiR eht htiw ecnadrocca ni gnicnad ym decitcarp daetsni dna
.egdelwonk fo ekas eht rof modsiw ot dednilb neeb dah I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.dog eht fo eman eht ni detalupoc neve dna
”.seY“ .mih rof si sihT
.su dnuora seohce gninthgil fo leep eht dna
.nwod eciov sih peek ot wol sessih eh ”?yhW“ .gib seye
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,lautir eht fo trats eht gnilangis ria eht taeb smurd ehT
.niatnuom eht fo skcor eht otni tuc neeb sah siad a ,ratla eht evobA
,sbreh gnitacixotni htiw decal ylbissop ,gnorts saw eniw ehT
,rentrap tnanimod eht fo elor eht sah eH
.drow rehtona tuohtiw
suhccaB fo ecivres eht ot efil ym etoved llits I“
.seye ym fo segdir eht gnola ruf eht ecart ot nwod sehcaer eH
.truh lliw siht ,xaler t’nod I fI
.flesym noitom eht taeper I ”.ydaer ma I“
”.sruof lla no uoy tup ot gniog m’I“ ,em ot syas eh
.ylthgit wap ym sezeeuqs sinaS
,su erofeb yal gnihctaw era sdog eht taht sngis eht ,ydaerlA
.taeb eht ni pu thguac
.nwod swols eh dna ,drah oot em gnihsup s’eh mih gninraw
.pu nesool nac I os stsurht eh elihw elcric a ni dnuora spih sih skrow eH
etisbew sih no dnuof eb nac gnitirw sih tuoba noitamrofni dna
.deudbus era stnecs ruo os
.suhccaB fo eutats eht no kcab sucof I erofeb mih revo tfird seye ym gnittel
”?suhccaB htiw yllaer tirips ruoy si tub
.gnorts eb ot dah I tub
.wonk ylerab uoy namow a htiw siht ot od ydaer erew uoY“
.gnola em gnillup ,ffo sllor eh erofeb yllacitore em kcil ot sdeecorp eh dna
.su dnuora sehsalf gninthgiL
”.efilretfa eht ni uoy evres dna og ylgnilliw lliw yeht
.ria eht no niar fo tnecs eht llems nac I
”.etiR eht pots ot yrt ot gniog ma I
eht fo stceffe eht morf gninnips si daeh yM
,gnilpuoc eht dna ecnad eht retfA
.rehto hcae erofeb dekan won era ew dna
emas eht seod sinaS
tseirp hgih eht fo sebor ehT
?egdelwonk fo tiusrup eht ni ,yllacirohpatem tiebla
,sebor ruo evomer ot nigeb dna pu emoc stnadnetta owT
.suhccaB ot tnemtimmoc sih
.sdog eht teem ot su rof emit si tI
.ruf ym hguorht dees gniliart
llorcs eht pu llor I
.emit siht ton tub ,pot no yllausu saw I ,tsap eht nI
.noitisop tnanimod eht ni em htiw emit siht
,ecnadnetta ni era suhccaB fo setaitini dna stseirp eht fo llA
.su sksa eh ”?ydaer uoy erA“
.taorht ym ni sehctac htaerb yM
.elbmut I dna kcab em speews eh
,llews ot strats ti ecno ecnis melborp a osla si tonk siH
.evol sih gninrups yliratnulov saw I sa neve em yb kcuts eH
.tey tnecs ym thguac t’nsah eH
.ezingocer I eciov a stuohs ”!sdog eht ot og yam gnilliw eht ylnO“
.diputs os neeb t’ndah I fi dereetnulov evah dluow reven eH
.ecnetnes taht etelpmoc t’nac I dna em sessik eh ”...evil ydaerla eW“
.elpmet eht ssorca wolb sevael yrD
,dehtab yllacitsilautir htob evah eW
.xaler dna yrt dna htaerb ym ni kcus I
.ni tonk eht pils ot hguone esool em tog s’eh ,etunim a retfA
.em morf yawa tsaf gnippets ,ffo snips eh dna ,og mih tel I
,drah gnihtaerb llits ,seenk ym no nwod teg I ”.naksA ,leenK
.tseb wonk I tahw ot denrut evah I
,hguone llat ylerab si eH
”.sdeen nwo ruoy evres ot si ti kniht I
;dnim gnileer ym ydaets ot yrt I
peed ni sehtaerb eH
,ti morf sknird dna
,ylkciuq gnippets
,yks eht ni sehsalf gninthgil sa neve
.moc.gnirpsyad-seyethgin
.struh llits ti tub
.thgiled dna regnuh htiw su nopu kool yeht ees nac I
.mih ta pu kool dna
”?etiR eht mrofrep ot hsiw os uoy od yhW“
.seye ym nepo I
.srae ym ni gnidnuop traeh ym raeh nac I
.skrow siht epoh ylno nac I
em ta skool sinaS
.ecnatsid eht ni gninthgil fo sehsalf era ereht
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.elpmet eht fo edis eno no stis ,flow a
.nwod ti secalp dna ratla eht ot sklaw eH
:yojne esaelP  .sinaS evas dna
.ni neeb evah I noitisop enorp eht morf pu teg I sa dnuora gnikool sinaS ot yas I
”,evil ot su rof sehsiw sseddog ehT“
.em detcejer d’ehs nehw reh evres ot ydaer ton saw I nwonk dah sseddog ehT
.dekan ,gnitnap dnats I
…sseddog eht ot tseretni fo yltnecer os enO
.daeh ym srevoc taht dooh a dna
.sduolc krad eht ni kaerb a hguorht senihs noom eht
.nwod eciov ym peek ot deen t’nod I os ,etal si tI .mih ot llac I
.lio evilo htiw dellif si lwob eht em sllet eson yM
retal sdnoces dna smra ym fo og stel eh pots I nehw dna
;teiuq si yrarbil ehT  2 fo 2 traP
,siad eht ot kcab spets tseirp hgih ehT
.thguoht ni peed
”.rentrap elamef a htiw citsaisuhtne sa eb t’now eH“
”sdoG eht fo yrolG“
.dworc eht morf drawrof spets tsireM
.cisum eht ot mhtyhr peek ot gniyrt ,kcab ,knirhs I
.emoh ruo ot kcab niar eht hguorht ylwols klaw ew dna
.smurd eht fo ecap eht no pu skcip eh
.suhccaB evres ot toN“
.kaeps ot mih rof stiaw enoyreve dna ,sllaf hsuh A
”.suhccaB ot htao eht koot I .deksa I esuaceB“
”,won sekatsim ym ezilaer I uoy wonk uoy tel ot
gniwolb si dniw ehT
.su nopu era seye s’enoyrevE .don I
.lwob eht gniyrrac em ot revo kcab semoc eH
.eurt saw taht ,dereetnulov I nehW
.drah ylluf ton m’I tub ,lausnes hcuot sih dnif I .revihs I
.pu gnikcip si dniw ehT .syas eh
,sevom sih ot gnola wollof I
,niaga hcuot seidob ruo sA
.flesmih gniraperp neeb sah eH“ .sgurhs xof ehT
,hcaorppa ot gnitrats si mrots ehT
”.evig ot enim regnol on si tI
stseirp eht fo tser eht dna
,efil txen eht ni sdog eht evres ot era ew fi dna
.rehtegot os od lliw ew
,remmus fo noom lluf tsrif eht gnirud raey a ecno demrofrep si lautir ehT
.stseirp eht fo dworc eht peews seye yM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.efil txen eht ni mih nioj ot sa os
.tluC eht fo trap a emoceb ylluf ot deen I
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.tsirw eht no em sehctac eh dna
,ylyoc elims dna
”.uoy rof tseb ym od lliw I
.siad eht fo daeh eht ot pu sklaw tseirp hgih ehT
.yas nac I tahw wonk t’nod I ”…ehs ,ehS“
,noitaitini ym ecnis syad eerht neeb sah tI
.naksA ot sgnoleb traeh ym won tuB
mih ta ecnalg I
.em sesaeler neht eH
.tneserp lla era gnihctaw era sdog eht sngis ehT
.yaw rieht no tnes era lautir eht demrofrep evah ohw esoht fo sdriht-owt revo sraeppa ti
.riap eht neewteb gnilpuoc a ni gnitluser
”?dereetnulov uoy yhw taht sI“
,noitrexe dna lohocla
.dnim ym morf thguoht taht hsup I
”sdoG eht fo yrolG“
edis eht morf segreme tseirp A .yltnelis wob eW
rettiwT no dnuof eb nac eH
.ruf ruo gnilffur
.sdnah sih ni sevil ruo sah eh dna
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
”.edam sah sinaS eciohc emas eht edam oot uoY
.srettam yllaer tahw ot sllorcs eseht dnoyeb ees em depleh evah uoY“
”.ecivres sih otni uoy tpecca eh yam dna ,llew ecnad os
.yas nac I gnihton si ereht tub
.niorg ym ni nwod si elzzum sih
gnorts swolb dniw ehT
.lautir eht wonk t’nod uoY
.sevom decitcarp-llew fo seires a hguorht ydob sih gnipool
.gnineppah eb t’nac sihT .ereh eb t’nac uoY“ .dekcohs em ta
,sinaS hctac I sa retsaf taeb smurd ehT
srecuas sa gib sa era yehT .seye sih otni kool I
yrautcnas roodtuo eht fo egde eht no gnidnats ma I
”.erom on suhccaB evres lliw I“ .sinaS syas ”...oN“
.doohrehtorB eht ot gnoleb ot gniog reven erew uoy nehT“
.sesnes dna seye eht rof tsaef a thginot uoy reffo ew ,dog eniw hO“
,lautir eht erofeb tuo gninnur emit htiW
.yas nac I lla si ”,seY“
.supmylO .tM ta sdog rehto eht dna mih evres ot
.sksa eh ”?sinaS ,ydaer uoy erA“
.stleb ruo gnivomer yb gninnigeb
,htiaf sih fo trap a erew sretnuocne lauxes ruo demussa dah
.lautir s’suhccaB gnikaerb yb sdog eht LLA gniregna ksir uoy taht dnim ni peek ,tuB
.daeh sih sekahs eH ”.evres oT“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
,em htiw siht od ot ydaer ton uoy erA
,nam lufrewop a si eH
.rettam t’nseod ti tub ,erew yllaer uoy fi derednow I“
”?nerdlihc ym ydaer uoy erA“ .emas eht od I
”?sey ,llorcS eht fo doohrehtorB eht rof detcejer erew uoy taht dnatsrednu I ,tuB
.pu em nesool ot gniyrt
,detatiga em ta slworg eh
,em dnuora elcric sih snethgit eh sa