.ylimaf ruo ecnavda pleh ot gniog reve saw I yaw ylno eht saw ebircs detaitini na gnieB
”.ytilarom no sweiv tnereffid yrev evah sdog ruO
ro suhccaB fo tluC eht nioj dna redisnocer ot uoy gniggub tpek I yhw s’tI
,uoy htiw dlrow siht ni yppah eb t’ndluoc I fI .dereetnulov I
?taht od uoy dluow yhW
.ssendam dna ysatsce citsilautir yb tub
”.gnihtyreve tuoba esae hcus evaH“ ”?tahw oD“
,detpecca eb ot reisae si tI“
.neht ecnis hcum denrael dna nees evah I dna
diulf tub citats reven si ecnalab tahT“
,noom dna tnuh eht fo sseddog hO“
”?eh t’nsah ,gnoS eniW eht fo etiR eht rof detceles neeb sah eh
,em fo retteb eht steg ytisoiruc yM
.modsiw ruoy skees etyloca siht
.etiR eht gnimrofrep erofeb
,tnemom siht ot pu del sah efil ym ni gnihtyrevE
”?redro ruo otni naksA tpecca uoy od ,sseddog hO“ ”.ma I“ ”?ediug ylno ruoy eb ot modsiw rof ydaer uoy erA“ ”.ma I“ .em
.thgin on eb nac ereht ,yad eht tuohtiW
driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[   .moc.gnirpsyad-seyethgin
,suhccaB fo ratla eht no flesym etacilppus ot nwo ym no delevart I
,raeb eht ta pu kool I
.neppah lliw tahw wonk meht tel dna
”.raey txen nioj ot dlo oot eb lliw I ,tuB“
.shtiaf eht fo tnanet nwonk-llew a si sihT ”.esruoc fO“
”.ylesnemmi suhccaB desaelp sah gnicnad ym leef stseirp hgih ehT“
,taorht ruoy tils nac yeht os elbram fo kcolb a no nwod yal ot gniog era uoy taht em gnillet
nekat eb t’ndluohs snoitca emoS
.srehto eht htiw flesym erahs ton did I tub
.lautir eht no sucof ot deen I .elzzum ym gnippid ,daeh ym rewol I
,tbuod swohs reven eH
.smra sih sesiar raeb eht sa seltsur cirbaF
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,elihw a retfa smra sih
,hguoht dedaf sah ruf siH .eno der a tub
.sdnah gnikauq sih seidaets dna flesmih sekahs eH
# ”.si taht yhw mih ksa dluohs uoy spahrep nehT“
.polf srae ym gnittel ,daeh ym ekahs I
.suovren si eh evah I tnih ylno eht si tI
”.suhccaB fo eman eht ni flesruoy detarcesed evah uoY“
.eman s’dog eht ni dleh erew taht seigro eht dna ,gnicnad eht ,eniw eht
yrautcnas emas eht ni detacol era selpmet owt eht tcaf ehT
.ylleb ym ni regnuh fo gnileef gniwang eht dah syawla I ,pu gniworG“ ”.oN“
rekcilf sreizarb ehT
”.redro tnereffid a nioj ot eerf er’uoy won ,oS“
?em tpecca ehs t’ndid yhW
.htap tnereffid a no em detnaw ehs suoivbo saw ti
.sdnal ruo tirehni dna eman ruo no yrrac ot ereht era srehtorb yM
”,neht elihw a rof nwonk s’eH“
,gnas I dna ,knard I ,decnad I“
,hself eht fo tiusrup lausnes eht secarbme tluc enO
was yeht tahw dekil stseirp ehT
.od ot ereh emac I tahw s’tI“
.em deined neeb s’ti won dna
.stsevrah doog rof gnipoh
”.ngis a edam evah dluow ehs ,dah ehs fI
”.eseht gniyduts yb ylpmis rof eraperp t’nac uoy stset htiw uoy tneserp llits yam ehS
.htap nwo sih wollof ot tfel tub
,suhccaB fo etaitini na emaceb I nehw stbuod fo ytnelp
,sinaS ,dneirf …ruoY
,em fo tnorf ni dnuorg eht no
”.decitcarp si ti dlot ma I sa etiR eht gniwollof era yeht fI“ .sdon tsireM
,rehtegot tuh moor eno elttil ruo ,esuoh ehT
”.truh taht wonk uoY“ .elbmurg I
.naksA taht ni emahs on si erehT“
.ylhsipeehs yas I ”,elttil A“
”.naksA ,enola em evaeL“
,ti od ot sdeen enoemoS
.liat sih skcilf sinaS ”…woN
,pu smra sih stfil raeb ehT
.ylgnivorppa gniddon syas eh ”,deednI“
,ereh si sseddog ehT
.mih reffo ot gnihtemos dah I dna
”sdoG eht fo yrolG“
”.ssenilnaelc fo esnes elbanosaer a niatniam dna ehtab ot uoy tcepxe I dna
.reh gnivres fo yhtrow era uoy leef ton seod ehs emussa ot kciuq oot eb ton oD
.em sraeh eh wonk I tub ,hcaorppa I nehw thguoht ni peed si sinaS
doohrehtorB eht ni ecno saw eh taht dlot neeb ev’I
.rednow s’suhccaB uoy htiw erahs
”?flesruoy devas naem uoy od tahW“ ”.tnuH s’anaiD
.sdrawkcab em gnihsup
”?em llet uoy t’ndid yhw …yhW
”.doohrehtorB eht nioj ot sehsiw eH
.yrc yltfos ot trats dna
.gninrub sreizarb eht htiw enola em gnivael ,yrautcnas eht fo tuo sklaw tseirp
”?taht lla fo tuo evah I tahw wonk uoy oD
,ni ehtaerb I  2 fo 1 traP
,nus eht tuohtiw tub
,emit fo htrow s’raey eritne na detsaw I evah ylno toN
!dnatsrednu t’ndluow uoy wenk I esuaceb ,uoy llet t’ndid I“
,llew decnad evah etaitini nigriv nesohc eht dna eh fi ,drawretfA
,yellav peed a gnikoolrevo edisllih a no si xelpmoc elpmet ehT
”.t’ndid ehs ,oN“ .em sksa eh
.slautir s’tluC eht fo ynam fo
sksa tseirp eht ”?ees ot diarfanu uoy erA“ ”.ma I“ ”?naksA ,traeh fo erup uoy erA
.etiR eht mrofrep ot ronoh taerg a si tI“ ’”.seY“
?uoy t’nod ,sseddog eht fo seye eht ni naelcnu uoy edam sah em htiw gnivil kniht uoY“ .shgis eH
”?etiR eht mrofrep ot gniog erew uoy nwonk uoy evah gnol woh ,sinaS
.redluohs ym no dnah a leef I nehw eltrats I os
.ylluferac tuo ti gnihsurb erofeb slio detnecs htiw ruf ym deifirup dna dehsaw gnivah
,hguoht oga gnol saw tahT
ton er’yehT .tnuH eht fo tluC eht nioj nac uoy spahreP
,em dniheb tuo peews liat ym gnittel
.efil ysae na t’nsaw ti tub ,def enoyreve peek ot tseb rieht did ylimaf yM
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
emoh nettirw ydaerla evah I“ .nosaer doog rof
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.meht snepo eh tub ,seye sih
,em ot txen nwod sleenk sinaS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,setarepo doohrehtorB eht yaw eht fo stcepsa niatrec tuoba noinipo fo ecnereffid a …dah I“
.mih ta pu kool I
”.etamesuoh rehtona teg ot gniog m’I ,tniop emos ta ehtab dna pu teg t’nod uoy fi ,wonk uoY“
,taeH ni deraeppa sah krow s’eyEthgiN
!htaed ruoy ot gniog yliratnulov era uoY“
.llorcs eht pu gnillor yas I ”,yrroS“
”.rof deniart evah I lla s’taht dna ,ebircs a eb ot em detnaw ylimaf yM
”.won esle enoyna eraperp ot etal oot si ti dna
desolc dah eH ”?ti od uoy od woH“
,gnicnad eht otni traeh ym tup I
.nruter ni ylimaf ym depleh sah eh dna
.wonk ot detnaw I lla em dlot taht dna
”?ti tuoba tespu m’I yhw wonk ot tnaw uoy dna
.detaremune ylraelc reven sdeedsim rof tuo tsac saw eh taht repsihw srehtO
tsireM knom dlo eht taht ees I dna
”?uoy llet ton did eH“ .yas I
,sretnuh dna sralohcs lanoitpecxe stfarc enO
xof roop a tsuj regnol on saw I
.yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I  ”.emit siht ta
,sbos tsomla eH ”…depoh I llits tub
”.sinaS ,raey elohw A“ .srae ym kcilf I
.poord srae sih eciton I dna ,revihs I
.deb ym si taht toc eht no hcamots ym otno revo llor I
.od lliw uoy tahw wonk syawla uoy tub ,seY“
.ydob sih srevoc ruf deroloc maerc ,yffulF
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
,wov eht koot uoy ,taht etipsed teY“
,esuoh eht fo tuo sklaw dna nrut eh
”.gninrael citsilautir no desucof os
”,gniyduts tnatsnoc taht lla staeb tI
!lakcaj hsiloof ,diputs uoy ,naksA ?sdneirF“
”?em llet uoy t’ndid yhW“
.sseddog eht fo yrautcnas eht ni em erofeb sdnats anaiD fo tseirp hgih ehT
.etihw htiw dekaerts won si dna
tuo dehcaer evah I
,noom eht erehw ot stniop eH
:yojne esaelP   ]yrtne
,tluC ot kcab flesym denepo dna slautir eht ot denruter I nehw tey
.nwod nettirw eb nac tahw dnoyeb seog modsiw eurt tub
.noisserpxe deniap a htiw em
”,yadot litnu toN“ .tsireM sksa
.snoitazilivic tneicna
xes morf gniniatsba yb wenk I
.llew yrotsih eht wonk I dna ,erofeb ti daer evah I
.noob s’sseddog eht eviecer ot ydaer ma I
.srebmem wen stpecca redro eht erofeb raey lluf a eb lliw tI
”.txen eht ni suhccaB evres dna og tsael ta dluoc I
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
.ti ni smelborp ym ot srewsna yna dnif t’now I
.noom on eb nac ereht ,nus eht tuohtiW“ .em sksa eh
saw I ohw tegrof ot dah I
.llorcs eht deppat eH
.naksA ,yrros m’I
,tnuh eht ot noitoved ro
.pu gnitteg yas I
ta skool sinaS .srecnad dna ,steop ,srekam eniw tseb eht fo detsaob rehto eht elihw
.egdelp ym ees ot ydaer ,su gnihctaw
sinaS ”.doog neeb evah emoh ta stsevrah eht neht ecnis dna
slworg cennef ehT
# .draytruoc detresed eht evael ot ygrene eht retsum nac I erofeb elihw a em sekat tI
.em sekop dna pu sklaw cennef ehT
”?shtnom owt rof gniraperp neeb sah sinaS“
eeffoc rof tnahcnep a evah ot deromur si ohw rekamelbuort nwonk a
,etiR eht mrofrep ot etaitini thguos yeht nehw dna
.enoyna naht selpmet eht tuoba erom swonk eh dna
.llaw eht ta erats tsuj nac I os
”.decneirepxe eb ot sah tI
?hguone doog ton I mA
,modsiw tuoba tol a sklat doohrehtorB ehT“
.em ta wol selbmurg cennef ehT
.pord srae ym leef I
?od ot em tcepxe uoy od erom tahW
.ereh yats ot em fo gnorw saw ti ebyam ,wonk t’nod I“
.maerts a ni retaw ekil
!uoy dnuora sehtolc gniraew ot koot neve I
!oga shtnom xis revo saw uoy dehcuot I emit tsal ehT“
.ereht emit elbaredisnoc sdneps eh dna
.gnilkcarc ylwols ,llits era yeht neht dna
.naksA ,levart ot daor ysae na ton si anaiD gnivreS“ shgis eH
,yrarbil eht esu mih tel llits srehtorb eht ,sseldrageR
”.sseddog eht tub tuo gnihtyreve hsup ot gniyrt dna
”.ot desoppus saw tI“
”!sdneirf erew ew thguoht I ,tuB“
suhccaB fo tluC eht yhw si tI
,etutsa si tsireM
# .dneirf tsesolc ym ekat noos lliw suhccaB tub ,em
sesoohc ehS .t’ndid uoy ebyam dna ,did uoy ebyaM“
,em detnaw llits anaiD taht traeh ym ni wenk I elihW
regnahffilc eht evloser sretcarahc[ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ fo strap # fo # eht eht saw sihT
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.pu flesmih werd eH
.enots dloc eht tsniaga gniyl
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna eseht piks nac uoy
.llorcs eht pu gnillor yletelpmoc morf em spots dna revo sehcaer eH ”.wonk I“
.egdelwonk fo evol ym tub gnihtyreve fo flesym gnigrup ,noitaitini eht rof gniraperp efil ym fo raey tsal eritne eht tneps evah I
.sebircs fo hcnub a tsuj er’yeht ,yawynA
rettiwT no dnuof eb nac eH
.traeh fo erup eb tsum uoy ,sseddog eht evres oT“
!loof diputs uoy oN“
.ynomerec eht nigeb ot ydaer
.desufnoc mih ta knilb I
”?gnoS eniW eht fo etiR eht mrofrep ot uoy deksa yeht … nioJ ?mih nioJ“
.evorg dercas eht ni eb lliw I os ,flesym eraperp tsum I“ .pu steg eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ti yojne dluow uoy ,won emoc hO“
,ti tseuqer yllacificeps taht setaitini ot nevig ylno si noitaredisnoc dna ,ronoh hgih a si gnoS eniW eht fo etiR eht gnimrofreP ”…I ,sinaS“ ”.htinez reh sehcaer noom eht nehw
taht ees dluow uoy depoh I“
er’uoY ?taht uoy ksa ot evah I od ,naem uoy od tahW“
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
”.taht ekil ti ta gnirats peek uoy fi tnemhcrap eht nrub lliw seye ruoY“
”.htob meht ekat sdog eht
.siht em ksa t’ndluow eh depoh dah I
.retaw gniwolf eht no gnisucof ot kcab seog eh erofeb em ta secnalg eH
,gnidnuorrus ym ot noitnetta gniyap neeb t’nevah I
.yrautcnas eht ot evom dna doohrehtorB eht gninioj etelpmoc dluow uoy thguoht I
.em ot syas eh ”,leenK“
”.wonk I“ .yltfos selims eH
,tnemtnioppasid ot snrut noisserpxe siH
.wonk t’nod I .redro ruo gninioj naht rehto uoy rof sngised tnereffid yleritne sah ehs spahreP
,ytitsahc deriuqer doohrehtorB eht taht wenk I …wenk I
.srebmem sti fo tol a sksa tluC eht tub
,drah em sevohs dna
.ylimaf dednal ronim yrev a fo nos driht eht ma I“ .daeh ym ekahs I
.sredluohs eht yb ylhguor mih barg I
,sekahs redluohs ym no dnah siH .ylkaew syas eH
”?doohrehtorB eht evael uoy did yhW“ ksa I dna
”.yrolg reh ni enihs tonnac ehs
,dog ym fo ecneserp eht tlef dna
”?suhccaB fo etaitini na emaceb I yhw wonk uoy oD“
.htnom a ni si yadhtrib ym dna
redro ruo otni uoy emoclew t’nac I dna
,lautir eht rof dekan ma I
,em ta detniop era srae gib siH
”.em tnaw dluow anaiD taht traeh ym ni thguoht I“
.em ta kcab kool t’nseod eH
,em sdrawot spets eH .dnats I .syas eh
.mih rof tuo gnihcaer llac I ”…sinaS“
,emoh ta hcaorppa tsedom erom a detpoda I
”?efil ruoy otni thguorb I snoitatpmet eht rof uoy detcejer ehs tahT
etisbew sih no dnuof eb nac gnitirw sih tuoba noitamrofni dna
”.od ot dah I gnihtyreve did I tuB“
”.naksA yrros m’I“
,drawrof spets tseirp ehT .don I
.od ot dah uoy gnihtemos t’nsaw taht
srewol tseirp eht sa cirbaf fo gnilffuhs eht raeh I .sseddog eht morf ngis on si erehT .sneppah gnihton tub ,tiaw eW .elkcarc serif eht dna ,llits si ria ehT
,daed ni tseretni na dna
”.tluC eht nioj ot em deksa dna
.em ot snrut dna spots tseirp ehT
,doohrehtorB eht nioj ot drah os gnikrow erew uoy esuaceb
:slautir eht tuoba elttil a em dlot dah
”.thgir mees t’ndid emit eht tub ,renoos uoy llet ot detnaw I“
.uoy tpecca t’ndid ehS“
.moor eht ssorca teem roolf eht dna llaw eht erehw ta erats I
.redro eht nioj t’nac uoy nehT“
.niorg sih ot level eye ma I dna
.em ta sgnaf sih serab eH
.kcab srae ym yal I
,lufrewop si noom ehT“
.esuoh eht otni stnecs egnarts yna gnirb t’ndid dna slautir eht retfa ylluferac hsaw ot erus edam I
worg t’ndluow separg eht nehw ,gnirps yrd enO
.redluohs ym sehcuot dna em ot pu sklaw eH
.nrael ot ydaer ro traeh fo erup uoy dnif ton did ehs spahreP
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
desucof llits ma I tub
,tiaW“ .yawa sklaw eH
”.esolc pu krowtoof ym ees yam eh os mih nioj dna og ot ma I“ ”?seY“ .don I
seye ym esolc I
.dessorc sgel sih htiw ,esop luftser ,teiuq a semussa eH
.sucof dna edisa flesym tup ot dah I tub
.mih ot txen nwod gnittis dna pu gnimoc ,yas I ”,yeH“
.rehto hcae ot setisoppo hcus ta dnats llorcS eht fo doohrehtorB eht dna
”.rehto hcae ot ecnalab a sa tca yehT
.no kooc ot su rof htraeh llams a dna ,stoc owt naht erom elttil si
.htap eht raen ssarg eht otno llaf I
tnaw ton anaiD seod ylno toN
”.htap reisae hcum a eb ot smees suhccaB fo etaitini na gnimoceB“ .hgis I
”?lakcaj ydaer uoy erA“ .gnitiaw
dah I“ .selkcuhc eH
.gnihtyna yas t’ndid I
hgih ehT ”.wollof dluohs uoy skniht ehs htap tahw dnif ot uoy ot pu si tI
.edis ym gnibbur yltneg wap a
”!siht od ot ronoh na si tI
”.tsael ta dehtab evah uoY“
.]resaet rehto ro
suhccaB htiw gninummoc dna slautir laiceps gnicitcarp ,gniraperp shtnom owt sdneps
”.etaitini na eb ot tnaw t’nod I
,ngis on saw ereht taht si wonk I llA
.gniltsirb ruf ,ffo sklats dna pu steg eH
uoy llet t’ndid I
.srehto ni hturt eht ees ot diarfanu eb tsum uoy ,swonk ehs tahw nrael oT
.ssol on eb nac ereht ,evol tuohtiW
ecivres ym hguorht wonk I dna
.srae eht neewteb drah em sffuc sinaS
redisnoc ot deksa saw I dna
.selkcuhc xof ehT
.elbaraeb raey taht edam ohw nosrep ylno eht esol noos lliw I
,yppah mih edam evah I
.tnemhcrap eht no nward si ,slobmys s’anaiD fo eno
.uoy tuoba klat s’tel ,seidob gnitarcesed tuoba klat ot tnaw uoy fi ,tuB
.elkcif si sseddog ehT
?thgir ,siht od ot dereetnulov I wonk od uoY“
,pu kool ot nrut I
.etiR eht mrofrep ot gniog llits ma I tub ,naksA yrros m’I“
.reh ot erom flesym dettimmoc evah dluoc I ekil leef I tub ,em pleh ot troffe taerg a edam ev’uoy wonk I
”.shtnom owt tsomlA“ .shgis eH
.roolf eht ot revo sgel ym gniws dna pu tis I
”.noihsaf emos ni doohrehtorB eht evres ot eunitnoc dna nruter ot elba neeb evah I
”sdoG eht fo yrolG“
”.em gnieb tsuj morf semoc tI“ .sgurhs eH
”?hguoht si taht yhw wonk uoy oD“
.em fo tnorf ni tnemhcrap eht ta erats I
,gnivres dedeen taht ereht tuo dog a saw erehT
.mih ta pu dekool tsuj I
.em tih eh erehw daeh ym bur I
”!yaw ruoy no uoy dnes ot etiR eht fo dne eht ta uoy llik yeht ,sinaS“
-tenibac a no renroc eno ni pu dekcats era sllorcs yM
.efil ym fo yad tseippah eht saw tI“ ,selims eH
egdelwonk rof tseuq eht hguorht ton nwohs saw suhccaB ot noitoveD
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”?uoy tceles ton did sseddog ehT .tespu mees uoY“
?llif ym teg t’ndluoc I esuaceb tsuj erew uoy no flesym werht dna slautir eht morf knurd emoh emac I semit esoht lla kniht uoy oD
”.dlrow eht ecnalabnu yeht ecnis
.enola em gnivael
.elzzum sih no kool lufepoh a
.liat deppit kcalb sih fo hsiws a htiw syas eh
.sraggeb roop tsuj naht erom era ew ngis ylno eht-
mih morf yawa llor dna trons I
.tnemom a rof tnelis si eH
.em ot pu deklaw sah
.egdelwonk fo tiusrup ciretose rehto eht elihw
.suhccaB fo elpmet eht raen sgnirps dercas eht yb sinaS dnif I
.ecivres fo seuneva rehto
.toc sih no nwod tis ot
,doohrehtorB eht morf erom denrael I
!tnemtnetnoc evah I
.dnim gnicar ym llits ot gniyrt
.ti gnidaer ton ma I tub
.dluoc I wonk t’ndid I sgniht emos dna ,retsum dluoc I gnihtyreve dog eht evag I .did I tahT“
”.uoy htiw yal ot tfel erised lacisyhp eht evah dluow I
.uoy htiw eb dna emoh emoc dluoc I os kcab dleh I
,sraey ynam retfa taht dalg ma I ,llitS
.doohrehtorB eht denioj uoy retfa litnu tiaw ot detnaw I tub ,uoy llet ot gnitiaw neeb evah I gnihtemos si erehT“
.won niav ni neeb evah ot sraeppa taht llA
.llorcS eht fo doohrehtorB eht nioj nac enoyreve toN“
”.dog eht ot ydob ruoy evag uoY“ .gnorw …demees tI
seod ohw recnad ehT
”,dnats yam uoY“ .gnitiaw
,esu uoy edam yeht lio detnecs taht fo knits uoY
”.gnihton si ereht woN
,seenk htob no nwod teg I
,uoy dlot ev’I ,suhccaB fo tluC eht gninioj tuoba si siht fI“
.dnuora gninrut ,mih ot yas I ”?ti s’taht
,emoh ruo fo ssol eht gnicaf erew ew dna
!ecaep evah I tub ,uoy htiw kcahs elttil siht ni evil yam I
moor eht fo edis rehto eht ot seog eH
.dlrow ruo ecnalab sgniht esehT
,nioj nac ega fo sraey eno-ytnewt naht regnuoy esoht ylnO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.no swolf syawla tI
.egduj ot ecalp ym t’nsi ti tub
.ylluferac srewollof reh
.rof deksa ehs gnihtyreve did I
”?won emoh og uoy lliW“
dluoc I os slautir eht morf emoh delbmuts I dna
.yrautcnas eht edisni dniw fo tsug a si erehT
”.tbuod wohs reven uoY
”.htrow s’ti tahw rof ,uoy ot esuoh eht evael lliw I
,llorcS eht fo doohrehtorB eht fo yrotsih eht sliated tI
,sdog eht deifirolg yrehcuabed citsilautir woh
.noitseuq eht ta esneffo on sekat eh wonk em tel ot selims eH
”.modsiw reh kees ohw esoht lla tpecca ton seod ehS
trap tnatropmi na era sgnirps eht dna
!flesym devas I ,oN
.ediug ylno ruoy eb tsum modsiW
.sdog eht htiw elor sih fo erus os ,mlac os si sinaS
,sinaS ekil xof a si knom ehT
.llorcs eht pu gnillor sehsinif knom dlo ehT
eeffochtiwflow@ ta
.suoludercni ,em ta kool ot snrut eH
.ereh demrofrep slautir suoigiler eht fo ymotohcid eht swohs
,hself eht fo snoitatpmet eht ot ni evig regnol on dluoc uoy em dlot uoy ecnis revE
.enola lla eb lliw I nooS
”?taht em ksa ot evah yllaer uoy oD“
,gnignis ym ,gnicnad ym saw dah I llA .ytpme tlef I
,syad ruof nI“ .ylegas sdon eH
.ylimaf ym rof dia gnikees
.decnalab eb tsum osla sdog ehT
”.dog eht fo tnavres a sa elor ym ecarbme dna
,etaitini na emoceb ot noisiced ym detterger reven evah I
.noitseuq tuohtiw mih fo deksa si tahw seod dna
,yas ot tahw fo kniht nac I erofeb dna
.seigolohtna rehto dna gnaF
.daeh sih sekahs dna ,redluohs eht no em stap
.smaerd ruoy gnillifluf uoy morf noitcartsid a tsuj emaceb I dna
.tluC eht rof sevil rieht nwod yal elpoep ekam t’nod yehT
”.sinaS ,em tnaw ton seod sseddog ehT
dootsrednu reven evah I .daeh ym ekahs I
.t’ndah I fi yrarbil eht ni kcab em tel evah t’ndluow yeht ,seY“