?ton ro ssorg erew sanigav ro slrig rehtehw egduj ot I saw yltcaxe ohW
.nyliraM ot maS morf dekool I
,hctans suoicsul mraw taht otni ecirht
.gniggas noitcere ym ,em erofeb thgis eht ta tsahga derats dnA
!taht od ot scirtaeht gnikcuf hcus…hcus hguorht og ot evah t’nod uoy ,maS
.wols ti ekat ot dah ew hguoht ,noitauqe eht deretne llits sedis ruo no gninoops
sbuc detnawnu yna no luof gniyrc ydal siht tuoba rednow dluoc I erofeb dna ,steehs ruo otno ylsuoipoc delbbird tI
.evol I nosrep eht morf tnereffid yna mih ekam t’nseod taht tub ,thguoht ecno d’I noitatneiro lauxes eht fo eb ton yam maS
.oot ssorg er’ohw nem fo ytnelp nwonk ev’I ,uoy dniM“
,iruaR nosmirC yb uoy rof daeR
.wenk ew elpoep fo seiceps rehto sa gniyalpelor
,lley ot gnitrats saw I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
,mih no esirprus ym gnirps ot em rof dnuorA
.hctans s’nyliraM htiw eit a otni dekcol saw tonk yM
.ni edils ot hguone gnilaeppa taht dnif dluoc enoyna yltcaxe woh tsuj gnirednow
.mottob ro pot ylevisulcxe erew su fo rehtieN
.dloh koot muc ot egru lamirp eht sa kcab nworht daeh ,delwoh I sa emit tsal eno demmals dna egde eht ot gnitserc flesym tlef I
”.mmu os ,dneirflrig ruoy si nyliraM tuB .od yllaer I ,maS od uoy sa uoy dnatsrednu ot tnaw I“
.reffo ot sah efil lla ecneirepxe ot eno swolla dnim nepo na gnipeek semitemos tub ,saw maS sa ib neve ro ,thgiarts eb ton yam I
.kcab pets evixelfer a koot I dna ,naitaslA eht delrans ”.ereh em tuoba yrrow ot deen on
.yrros kool ot ycneced eht evah tsael ta dluohs eh ,em no taehc ot enod dah maS tahw retfa taht tlef I tub ,em ni ahplA eht saw ti ebyaM
,msagro delgnim ni drawrof despalloc ehs sa enihw tuo-nward gnol a evag naitaslA ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,flesruoy eb syawlA .hsinif ,gnilwoh
;syug rehto htiw dnuora loof dluow maS taht deraef syawla I
,tihs rehto yna ot denetsil reven maS nevig ,gnisirprus oot t’nsaw hcihw
.sgniht tuoba dnim nmad nwo sih pu ekam t’ndluoc maS esuaceb ylno fi ,dehctaw ew seivom eht no dediced I
,gnizama na ot ffo mih dekorts I sa neve
.hguoht ,stnaruatser fo eciohc eht no nwod swap sih tup eH
.htaerb peed a gnikat ,opmet a pu tliub I sa smra reh htiw drawnwod em dexaoc nyliraM dna ,stsurht latnemirepxe lareves evag I
.noitacidni yna saw kcocnomed dilef debrab thguob-ylwen ym fo eman eht fi
.wonk t’ndid I elamef modnar emos gnikcuf dneirfyob nwo yrev ym saw ti taht tcaf eht tegrof
no repparw mgarhpaid ytpme eht was I
.dedracsid evah ew snoitatcepxe eht yb
.ma I yaw eht tsuj s’tahT .em ot tnatropmi os ti yhw dnatsrednu ot uoy tnaw tsuj I dna ,nemow dna
.reh sdrawot em llup ot tuo dehcaer nyliraM
,xes ahplA pota agemO etanoissap fo thgin a gniruD
”!em llet gnikcuf si od ot evah uoy llA
.stneve fo nrut suolucidir siht ta denettalf srae yM ”,—I—hW“
.kcab shtnom tuoba deklat d’ew tahw nevig ,gnihsinotsa taht lla t’nsaw sruof lla no enoemos ta yawa gnidnuop ,deb ruo no dekan saw eh taht tcaf eht nevE
.deralb cisum kcor duol hcihw nihtiw ,moordeb ruo erofeb thgir deppots I
,gnimoc saw I wenk eh fi esirprus a t’nsaw ti ,lla retfA
dedeen dneirfyob ym llA
.edis sih ot dellor eh sa maS dias ”,enim fo eugaelloc emit-gnol a s’nyliraM“ .edisdeb eht
.delwoh dna drawrof spih sih demmals eh euc no fi sA
.hcaeb eht ta gnillihc fo daetsni loop eht ni gnimmiws
.ahplA otcaf-ed eht gnieb ym htiw emac taht ysuolaej dna ssenevitcetorprevo taht s’ti spahrep
.em rof hserf sgniht peek ot nrut s’nyliraM dna sih won saw ti spahrep taht dezilaer dna ,hserf sgniht gnipeek yrt ot em wolla ot maS gnillet derebmemer I nehT
.ot elbanu flesym dnuof dna—
”.wohs eht yojne dna taes a ekat tsuJ“ .sffup dna sffuh neewteb ni maS dias ”,yrraH ,ylrae kcab er’uoy ees I“
,era ew sa gnuoy sa gnieb tub ,taerg saw xes eht ,eruS
.tuo dnif ot yaw eno ylno saw ereht dna os nyliraM hsivar dna hsirehc mih edam tahw dnatsrednu ot maS ot ti dewo I tuB
,koot I evom yreve
;enif saw taht tuB
.desnet I sa reh otni tfahs ym gnidiug nyliraM ,deb eht otno delwarc I sa gnikorts ym ni desuap I
.swodniw edis eht hguorht dereep I sa talf srae ym gnipeek ,esuoh ruo fo rood eht ot pu tperc I
otni muc fo tnerrot retfa tnerrot gnitrups kcid fo sdnuos delffum eht raeh dluoc I thguoht I sa neve denettalf srae yM
eno siht piks esaelp
.mih ot taht evig ot tseb ym od lliw I dna
.em erofeb krab a htiw gnimmuc ,dekcuf I sa ffo flesnwo sih gnikrej gnitrats d’ohw maS ta ylizah dekool I .moor eht gnitaemrep senomorehp fo sffihw
—edis ym ot llor ot edam I sa elims tub pleh t’ndluoc I dna
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
,floWisakiM yb ”syaW htoB gnioG“ saw sihT
.yflow ym fo ngis yna rof thgir dna tfel gniffins dna gnikool ,esuoh eht tuohguorht deotpit I ,nwo yrev ym htiw emit ni gnicnuob kcid citehtsorp yM
,elihw a rof looc gnikcuf saw ti tub ,ruf revo ruf gniraew ,driew gnikcuf tlef tI
.gniticxe dna hserf sgniht peek ot si
,derac taht esoht morf ecnatpecca saw
”…pu…reh…gnikconk ,ma I ereh dnA“
.selpuoc redneg-emas gnoma neve dednetxe ylsuoicsnocnu hcihw ,metsys kcap lahcrareih a dah yllanoitidart ew taht saw sevlow tuoba gniht eno tuB
dah sdinac lla draeh I roiretni s’yssup reh fo pmub eltbus ehT
,krow morf denruter rehto eht nehw rood eht fo tnorf ni thgir afos eht no dekan-ttub gniyl sa ekil ,ylmodnar rehto hcae gnisirprus ot koot neve I dna maS
.neht dna won yreve pu sgniht gnihctiws nageb ew oS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.noitnetta s’maS tog enocilis fo hctolps duol eht dna ,roolf eht ot no yenom detsaw ev’I kcoc nomed eht gnulf I
.detaretier I ”!ssorg era slriG“
,latnem gnikcuf uoy erA ?taes a ekaT“
.yalpelor dna ytivitca lauxes fo tenet yreve ot gnirehda ,sehctiws elitasrev ytterp erew eW
.ffo syad sih no yllaicepse ,kaerf taen a fo gnihtemos saw maS tcaf eht rof ton ti erew gnisirprus neeb evah t’ndluow hcihw ,moor eht dnuora derettacs erew gnihtolc fo selcitra fo elpuoc A
flow a ,floWisakiM yb ”syaW htoB gnioG“
.elihw siht lla em ot deil dneirfyob nmad ym nehw ton ,siht tuoba trops doog a eb ot deen eht leef t’ndid I tuB
.retirw yranecrem
,tnemeticxe retaerg ot stsurht ym del ,ssel on kcid ym dnuora gnihsols muc sih
,erus rof s’taht ,tihs yzarc fo sdnik lla deirt eW
!ma I ereh ,ton ro ydaeR“
,ton naht netfo eroM
.spruls dna skcams fo yrrulf a ni em gnisaeler dna gnipolevne xes reh fo taeh dna ssenmraw gnissapmocne yklis
.emoh s’eh snaem hcihw ,ereh llits saw rac s’maS
.yako tuo dekrow sgniht os ,srehto fo troppus eht su deniag tub ,sdneirf fo elpuoc a su tsol tI
.ni neeb d’ti eloh gnitsugsid tahw tsuj gnirednow ,htaehs sti otni kcab ylwols gnidecer tfahs ykcits s’maS ta dekool ylsuoicsnocnu I
”!ybab ,em rof yenoh taht fo emos peek ,aohW“
,hgih wen hserf a em evag lrig a gnikcuf em ffo tog maS taht tcaf ehT
.cilbup ni gnissik detrats ew litnu thgir ,srehtorb rof su kootsim netfo elpoep taht ekila os dekool su fo owt ehT
,seirogetac yb detimil eb ot esufer ot ,sevlesruo enifed ot ytiliba ruo si fo duorP eb ot sgniht eht gnomA
.nossel tnatropmi na tnrael I ,yad taht nO
.tsetorp ot edam I sa maS dias
,won sraey 5 rof rehtegot neeb dah I dna maS
.era ew ohw fo trap si tI
”.dnatsrednu esaelP .efil ym lla uoy morf terces a siht peek ot tnaw t’nod I tuB
”.yrraH wonk ydaerla uoy ,nyliraM
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.did I sa hcum sa sesirprus eseht ot drawrof dekool maS erus saw I dna ,su fo htob eht rof oobakeep tluda fo emag a yllacitcarp saw tI
,edam I tsurht reve detautcnup
.ssa s’naitaslA eht no edam maS kcilc dna pmuht ytaem
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.taht retfa keew a rof talf eil ro tis dluoc I dna maS rehtien ,tihs on dna ,gnitsif deirt neve eW
,eciwt ,ecno detrups I
.guh a otni su ward ot deb eht otno debmilc maS sa ylgnisaet niorg ym dnuora ruf eht gnikorts sregnif reh ,em ta dennirg naitaslA ehT
.relaed ssalc-rehgih sih morf erucorp ot deganam sdneirf ssalc-rehgih ym fo eno top no hgih nehw neve ro ,knurd elihw xes gnivah gnidulcni
.denigami evah reven dluoc I gnihtemos saw enoemos taht morf gnimoc spsag dna snaom eninimef-oot-lla ehT
-yb derevocsid eb ot sgniht eht ,tniop ni esaC
?elbissop saw taht wenk neve ohW
.ot enola og ot evah dluow I gnihtemos saw ycips ylrevo gnihtynA
.dehcnilf I sa sredluohs ym rof tuo gnihcaer swap ,em ot pu deklaw dna pu tog maS ”,yrraH“
.dednim-esolc sa regnol on erew elpoep nehw degnahc taht llA
.yarts ot dednet seye ruo tnaem neht dna won yreve yteirav elttil a evah ot deen eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tsrubtuo siht ta pu kcab desiar tub
.maS dias ”.ib m’I esuaceB“
.ekops nyliraM ”.taht ekil lla ton er’ew tub ,eiteews ,elbbub ruoy tsrub ot yrroS“
,rehtona eno tsuj ot deit t’nerew ew os eno nepo na eb ot pihsnoitaler ruo ekil dluow eh taht dias neve maS ecnO
steehs eht gnippirg swalc reh
.ereht tuo enoyreve ot ti tuoba nepo ylemertxe gnieb dna ,xes etanoissap hcum os gnivah maS dna em htiw tahw ,suoivbo eht gnitats ekil hcum oot mees thgim tI .od ro yas yam srehto tahw rettam on
.saw I sa lauqe na hcum sa saw maS ,deb ni tuB
.nyliraM teem ,yrraH“
,gnikib-niatnuom ro gnilcyc yrtnuoc-ssorc tnew ew rehtehw dediced ohw eno eht saw I
”!ti gid I tub ,evah uoy fo owt eht enituor driew emos eb ot skool tI
.laeppa rieht detimil fo dnik stiusruf repaehc fo tsoc eht neve hguoht
.yawyna rood egarag eht no dediced I ,eno on gniypS
floWisakiM yb ”syaW htoB gnioG“
,elyts-yobwoc em pota depmuls eh sa maS gnittonk ym ni gnidne
.tsael eht yas ot ,esool ylgnisirprus saw tI
sa lufetah sa tsuj saw thguoht fo niart lanigiro ym spahrep taht ,dezilaer I neht dnA
esuoh ruo fo syawllah eht detaemrep seiceps rehto fo taht elbmeser ot shtnom eht revo rehto hcae no desu d’ew secnargarf tnereffid eht lla fo stnecs eht ,revewoH ?thgir
.esuops gnitaehc sih no ni deklaw yug a retfa dewollof yllamron taht raef ro esirprus on detibihxe esiwrehto tub ,dellol eugnot reh sa em ta dekool lrig naitaslA ehT .detnap maS
,ti nmaddoG ?looC“
,em erofeb daerps yssup kcalb gninetsilg taht sa dekool I
asrev eciv dna ,ni kcid rieht kcits enoemos tel ew demussa yeht eloh hcihw dna devol ew ohw no desab su tsniaga gnitanimircsid ,larutannu em ekil syag deredisnoc dah elpoep ,ainnellim roF
.gniticxe sgniht peek ot ecnats ym ni dereviaw reve I
.saw taht eloh tahw-swonk-ohw
.htimS niatnuoM eht ,iruaR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer
.syug rehto htiw tnaem uoy thguoht I ,srehto htiw dnuora yalp dluoc uoy dias I nehW .tihs ytilacinhcet taht kcuF“
denedrubnu sevles citnehtua ruo drawot tnemirepxe ot
,nosirapmoc hguone doog a saw taht fi ,elohssa na naht resooL
.muc fo gniruoptuo na htiw tuo dellup maS sa liat dna wap a htiw devaw nyliraM
.sknik ruo no noissucsid suoires a rof emit hguone naht erom dah ew
mih no ni klaw ot uoy rof snalp yrassecen eht lla gnikam ksir gib a gnikat s’eh ,lleH
.’gniticxe dna hserf sgniht peek‘ ot tsuj
.desolc dna denepo htuom yM
.laiceps reh edam taht sedisni s’nyliraM fo secnereffid eht lla leef dluoc I dna
.gab krow ym fo tuo odlid htaehs krad-eht-ni-wolg a koot I sa rae-ot-rae ytniop morf gninnirg ,egarag eht ni sehtolc krow laireganam ym ffo gnileep saw I yhw saw hcihW
.esor ylidaets tfahs ym sa erusaelp s’maS gninigami ,drah ti depmup dna tfahs ym deppirg I ,mrots a tuo dednuop eh sa gnillol eugnot ,sselesnes nyliraM dekcuf eh sa ecaf s’maS no tnemyojne eht fo thguoht I sa dnA
,tontahw dna stnaruatser tuoba denoitnem ev’I sa ,stohs eht llac ot dah enoemoS
.bonkrood eht nopu wap ym decalp I sa ,noitcefrep elbanosaer otni kcab ti dekorts I ,maS evisule eht rof hcraes ym ni tahwemos deggas gnivah kcid yM
.ssel on evresed lla ew ,lla retfA
nepo eb ot tnatropmi si ti oS
,nwo yrev ruo fo tenet a koob ruo ot dedda sihT
”.ssorg reh dellac ylthgirtuo uoy ekil srehto nehw neve llihc ytterp s’ehS .ynnuf dna ,trams s’ehs ,ecin s’nyliraM .ees I lrig yna etad tsuj t’nod I .elpoep rehto gniees ot gnitnaw dna ,nepo pihsnoitaler ruo gnipeek tuoba uoy ot ekops ydaerla I“
.sselesu eson ym redner ot hguone
,hO“ ”.ssorg era slriG
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.lla retfa ,krow pihsnoitaler siht ekam ot denimreted saw I
.eporg a stit reh fo eno evag eh sa gnihgis ,ruf s’hctib eht hguorht swalc sih nar maS
.drow a neve saw taht fi ,ereh ebohplauxesib eht saw I ,gnihtyna fI
.moordeb eht ni hserf sgniht gnipeek ni tsetseb ym od ot ecnahc eht em evag eh sa gnol sa taht htiw enif saw I mih dlot I dna ,erus rof s’taht ,flow nwo sih saw maS .dednetni nup on
.tohsrae elbaredisnoc ym ni tsael ta
.edis rehto s’eno gnicarbme si hserf ti gnipeek ,semitemos dnA
.dekrab yllanif I ”?thgiarts erew uoy em llet uoy t’ndid yhW“
.em gniltrats ,dekrab maS ”!uoy esol ot tnaw t’ndid I“
,derahs ew oidar eht no yawa gnilwab saw sdnab etirovaf s’maS fo enO
,”stiusruf“ sa detekram semutsoc ni pu gnisserd deirt neve ew ,retteb tog yllanif sessa ruo nehW
.no nopu deerga yltnecer d’ew enituor a
.sselehtenon mraw dna toh tub
.noitulove nwo s’eno ot
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
,god.ecioveht ta
,reh htiw deris evah thgim maS
,ni dehsinif tsuj dah maS enoemos gnikcuf fo thguoht ehT
.ylurt sruoy morf tnemegaruocne emos htiw od dluoc eh dediced I
.ni degrab I sa decnuonna I ”!emoc uoy ekam ll’eh dna ,ereh si dalV
,ytrap etavirp s’enoemos ni redurtni detrevrep emos ,rueyov a ekil hcum oot leef ot gnitrats saw I
.boj wam ecin a htiw gninrom eht ni pu rehto eht gnikaw ro
—“ seye ym otni dekool eh ”—nem htob ni detseretni m’I“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.dehctiws eb selor ruo dluohs ,kcid rO .ssa eht ni doog mih tog I revenehw I naht reduol lwoh t’ndid eh fi nmaddog
;noitabrutsam lautum ,gnittorf ,lana ,larO
.sffur keehc dna elzzum detniop ,ruf yerg-ynwaT
.yznerf a ni—steehs ruo—
dracsid ot snoitatcepxe tsedrah eht tuB
.noitpo yna t’nsi reh htiw no ti teg ot em gnitcepxe oS“
”,yrraH ,uoy gnivol deppots reven ev’I tuB .elihw a gnitad neeb evah su fo owt ehT“
,ylfeirb denettalf s’rae s’maS dna
.reh gnidrocca I sffins kciuq wef eht morf ,wenk I kniht t’ndid I ,tsael tA
,relifed eht dalV tub ,ahplA eht yrraH t’nsaw I ,yadoT
yreve htiw gnilbbow sboob owt fo ecneserp eht yb dehsad saw noitanigami nwo ym fo tcudorp a eb dluoc ti taht ytilibissop ehT
”?tuoba deklat ew tahw rebmemer uoY .t’nia I oN“ ”?maS
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.ib sa uoy ot tuo gnimoc ym fo yaw looc ytterp a eb dluow siht thguoht su fo owt eht ,lleW“
;sih fo srettam gnidnatstuo emos elttes ot krow morf yad noitacav a nekat dah maS taht gniwonK
.hguoht ,taht retfa sgniteem ni ylsuoires mih ekat ot drah emaceb tI
.yg gnieb pleh t’nac uoy sa tsuj ,ib gnieb pleh t’nac eH !nosrep nwo sih s’maS ,yrraH ,no emoc tub ,uoy ot layol niamer ot tsuj su neewteb sgniht ffo ekorb ylraen eH .traehteews laer a s’eH ?maS ruoy tuB
taht ton ,hguoht skeew owt tsal eht rof em esirprus ot evird eht dah t’ndah eH
.niaga reve pu ti thguorb reven ,saw I taht trops doog eht ekil dna ,elims a dna pu sbmuht owt meht evag ylerem I
.em ot nyliraM morf dekool eh sa gnillol eugnot sih ,sriahc ruo fo eno no tas tsuj yflow ym tub ,maS ta ylgninoitseuq dekool I . ,daerps sgel reh htiw deb eht no kcab gniyl ,nyliraM delward ”?t’nia ti syas ohW“ ”.noitpo
.em ekil tsuj flow a s’maS
.htob su fo tnedifnoc ssel eht syawla s’maS
pihsnoitaler lufsseccus a ot yek ehT
.ereht tuo stihs cibohpomoh eht lla
.tesolc ecnanetniam eht ni ydal gninaelc eht gniod eugaelloc a no ni gniklaw ym detnuoc uoy sselnu ,dnim ,taht lla ni decneirepxe m’I taht toN
.evah ew ezilaer ton od ew esoht eb nac
.tuoba rehtona eno redro dna tcerroc ot sruo fo tibah a sniamer llits ti ,ytilauqe lanosrep tuoba lla er’ew hguoht dna
.deffuh maS ”,yrraH ,ti yrt uoy llit ti kconk t’nod ,haeY“
.reh no ksum s’maS fo senotrednu eht rof tpecxe ,no em denrut tnecs s’nyliraM tuoba gnihton ,tfahs ym no tlef I gnileef pruls pruls eht morf edisA
.did ew sa gnol sa rof rehtegot gniniamer ysae t’nsaw ti dna