,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.haeY" ".reve ton ebyaM
,yawa deklaw eiggaM ".eeffoc
.elbuort ni flesmih gnitteg sknurd rediputs s'nwot eht fo eno tuoba yrots a dlot eh sa wolg tesnus ylrae taht ni mih gnihctac
.mih ta pu dekool ehS ".haeY" .dehgis ehS ".wener
.yrros m'I .em rof toN"
.nruter ni sreh dezeeuqs eH ".flesruoy
".dehsimaf m'I !tae dluohs eW"
.seod ti esoppus I" .delkcuhc ehS ".won
.ruf keehc sih elffur ot tuo dehcaer dna dennirg ehS
,wap sih koot dna delims ehS
.sregnif sih ssik ot wap sih detfil dna delims ehS ".emoh
?eivom a dekcip uoy dnA" .delkcuhc ehS ".elihw
.evird gnol eht fo ecneulfni eht tuo gnihsurb
,elpuoc euqserutcip a erew yehT
notgnihsaW ot no tsae denrut ehS
:eilrahC saw tahT
.yletarapes tsuj ,enif eb d'yehT
,taes reh otni repeed elttil a delttes dna seye reh desolc neht ,eeffoc reh fo pis a koot ehS
.raw eht morf wef a neve dna
.ecilA dna neJ desiar dna
,reh ta dekool eH ".ti
.kcab dekcut era srae ruoy ,sediseB
.tops a uoy dnif ll'I tub
.kcul doog ,lleW" .mra reh dettap eiggaM
.tuo doots evah d'eh ,esenreB a sa dna
.rae reh deson dna krab lufeur ,tfos a evag naD ".yb seog emit sA
"?knird ot gnihtemos htiw ffo uoy trats I naC
"!niaga uoy ees ot taerg s'tI
.daed me' kconK .neJ ,oot ,uoy evoL"
,seye nworb tseb eht dah syawla dah naD .depoord srae
.spil reh dekcil neht ,delims naD ".naD
.deggurhs eh dna deggaw liat siH
,mih rof tiaw t'ndid ehS ".sraey
.elttil a uoy evol syawla ll'I
,irauR nosmirC yb
"?draeh t'ndah uoY
.epyt eht wonk uoY
.did uoy dalg m'I ,lleW"
.mehA .hA" .hguoc a sa ti revoc ot deirt neht
".emas eht deyats sah ecalp siht hcum woh tuoba gnikniht tsuj saw I sseug I"
,sklawedis eht dellorts sdik loohcs hgih fo spuorg llamS
.dah ti tahw ta kool og ot revo tnew ehs dna
"?evila me' kconk ebyam ,rE
.wodniw eht tuo dekool neJ
.uoy fo dnik ythgim s'tahT"
.taerg eb dluow eeffoc A ?he ,yad wolS"
.kcuts meht fo enon tub ,wef a neeb evah erehT .rerettalF"
.ti gniod peek ot tnaw I
.edis rehto eht dnuora ti dekrap d'eh ebyam tub
.serusaem flah yb gnihtyna od t'nod uoY
.tuo uoy ksa ot esucxe ym saw tI
,noitcelfer rieht was ehs dna ,krad hctip saw tI
dekriuq eiggaM "?ebyaM .mH" "?etad toh a no gnitiaW .yenoh ,eruS" ".sknahT"
eilloc htooms roloc-irt a
,dluoc yeht sa gnol sa ssik eht dleh yehT
?ti ekil uoy od dnA"
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.os sseug I" .delims ehS
.tfel d'ehs ecnis hcum degnahc t'ndah ylraelc ytnuoC nosreffeJ
,revo saw aeroK taht woN
;tfel I nehw sa lrig emas eht ton m'I
.skeehc tsur htiw elzzum depirts-etihw dna tlep kcalb cissalc eht htiw ,god tliub yldilos ,llat a saw eH
.ksa ot thguoht t'ndah ehS
.tsom naht retteb ylbaborp uoY
.dnim ruoy no gnihtemos tog ev'uoy nehw wonk I oS"
!wonk I" .delkcuhc ehS ".sesrun
neeb dah tI .devol syawla d'ehs seye nworb ,tfos
.sesrun decneirepxe erom esu dluoc yehT
,ni decnad t'nevah eW !ecnad s'tel tuB"
,regnis eht tsriF
.ylhguoroht rehtar sekarb eht detset ehs esuaceb ,ytpme saw daor eht gniht doog a saw tI
d'yeht nehw neetnac eht ni ralupop neeb dah "ognaT eulB"
,eno tsal eht htiw raw fo hguone dah gnivah
.kool lacizziuq a reh evag dna eeffoc reh gniruop dehsinif tsuj dah eiggaM
.ti ta doog eb ot mees I dna ,krow doog s'tI .ma I tahT"
,mmH" .ekops eh nehw ruf trohs reh no mraw saw htaerb siH
.gnar rood eht revo lleb eht nehw pu dekool ehs dna ,tol eht fo levarg eht hguorht dehcnurc seriT
.tseb eht ylno uoy hsiw I
.detrats cisum eht sa liat reh dna
.teertS egroeG nwod ylhtooms dellor rac wen s'retsis reH
"!sproC esruN ymrA eht otni tog uoy ees I
.hguone noos tuo dnif d'ehS  .ton spahrep
.ylkciuq doots neht
,ecneserp reh decnuonna rood eht revo lleb ehT
,syug fo tol a tem ylniatrec I
.tegdub rieht tif ti dna ,ecin yrev saw ti tub
”emoH gnioG“ saw sihT
.retrauq a ni deppord dna xobekuj eht ot revo tnew tub
dna 1 WALC dna 41 taeH ni seirots trohs sah ohw
.ecarbme railimaf
.drocer tsrif eht otno delttes eldeen eht dna
.swodniw nepo eht hguorht reh nioj nwot eht fo sdnuos eht tel dna evird reh fo redniamer eht deyojne dna
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
esruoc perp reciffo eht dna loohcs gnisrun morf seirots dlot ehS
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.won tnereffid gnihtemos evord eh ebyam ,kceH
.mra sih no wap a dial ehs tub
.nwod ti tes neht ,unem eht ta decnalg neJ dna
.redluohs sih revo mra eht revo wap a debbur ehS ".reverof
reh gnidloh saw eh rebmemer ot demees eH ".esirprus
.doog saw ti tub ,gniht ecin a t'nsaw tI
.retteb od dluoc ehs gnihtemos syawla saw erehT
.boj doog a evah uoy dna
mrofinu sih ni naD
.reh morf ssorca tis ot mih gnidiug
.9 sdrawot tfel denrut dna noitcesretni eht ot tuo dellup ehS .reh gnihctaw
.tressed a gnirahs eb ot demees elpuoc a ,renroc eno ni dna ,rab eht ta hciwdnas a no gnikrow god redlo na saw erehT
.seirots raw paws dna eno-no-eno rehtaf reh htiw pu hctac ot emit elttil a dah neve d'ehS
?uoy tuoba tahw dnA"
.worbeye na
"?dnim ruoy no s'tahW
.yrtnuoc reh dah ehs dna
.sraey xis sseug I ,llew
.ereh saw ehs yhw fo trap lla saw taht ,esruoc fO
,god emosdnah a neeb syawla d'eH
.delims dna esnopser ni deggaw ehS ".wonk uoY"
esaelp' :ydeen os lla erew yeht tub
,neJ ,uoy ssim ll'I" .dehgis naD ".seod
.rehtegot deppets yeht neht dna
"?tfel uoy erofeb ,sraey eerht ,tahw rof ylidaets detad eW
,naD ,ti teg em teL"
.stnemilpmoc htiw taerg neeb reven d'ehs ,naD morf nevE
,lleW .sgnos efas rieht htiw ,secnad loohcs hgih
.yawa deklaw ssertiaw eht sa delims tsuj neJ ".kcul
.ezeeuqs a wap sih gnivig
.ylrae rehtar m'I tub ,tib a ni em gninioj eb dluohs dneirf yM
.taes eht no gnipmuht liat yrehtaef
.egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy
.hguorht deppets naD
.naD ,uoy evol llits I wonk uoY"
.kcen sih fo ruf eht ta delzzun dna delims neJ ".gnikniht
.flesruoy fo erac doog ekaT .naD ,uoy evol I"
,taes eht morf tah sih derehtag dna
.wap sih dessik dna
.emit gnol a rof yawa neeb d'ehS
.hcum t'nsaw hcihw
,dworc raluger eht rof ylevil elttil a saw gnos taht desseug neJ
,sniatnuom eht sdrawot deppils nus eht sa naD dehctaw ehS
.ereh latipsoh wen a evah ew ,wonk uoY"
.esnopser eht ta gaw liat reh tlef ehs dna ,pu til ecaf siH
,airotciV droF 25' a saw ti
,dias uoy ekiL" .delkcuhc ehS ".tfel
,gib taht raeh
.gnileef doog a s'tI
,dlo taht otni delttes yeht dna ,denruter ehs nehw doots naD
.pu gnihctac htiw reppus ylrae na dessap yehT
,emosdnah denmad dna ,yug ecin a er'uoY
.sih fo htob neewteb ti gnihciwdnas ,wap reh derevoc eH ".gnileef
.enif tsuj dekrow yeht ,tuo denruT
.ssenyrw rof nrut s'naD saw tI ".boj
"?ynam woH  ?yenoh ,gniod ay woH"
.raw eht dna loohcs gnisrun neewteb
.wonk ydaerla t'ndid eh erahs ot gnihtemos evah ot desaelp saw ehs dna ,notgnihsaW raen nwod devil retsis reH
,ssik a tsuj si ssik A
.yltneuqerf saw hcihw ,t'nsaw eh nehw nwolc a dna
.sreh ni ehs dna
gniklat deppots d'eh gnizilaer erofeb ecnelis ni emit a rof mih ta derats ehS
.yleritne esle erehwemos er'uoy ekil kool uoy ,dias I"
.ma'aM .streboR tnanetueiL"
mra reh rednu revoc reh gnikcut
.dennirg ehs os ,yltnatcepxe reh ta gnikool ssertiaw eht dnuof ehS
.uoy tuoba emas eht leef I wonk uoy ,naD ,doG"
.noissimmoc reh wener ot dediced ehs fi noos niatpaC ekam d'ehs dna ,srab revlis reh denrae d'ehs ;dennirg ehS
.erutuf a dah yeht ylno fi
"?mmH" .yltnatcepxe reh ta gnikool saw dna
.reve sa tnarbiv sa tsuj tub
,yltneg kcen sih deppin ehS
si yrots s’yadot dna
.nosnaR fo htron tuo
.erus ,emit ot emit morf dad ruoy otni nur I" .dennirg eH
,redlo elttil a erew yehT
,sih tsniaga elzzum reh desserp ehS
.si ti tahT" .deddon neJ ".melborp
tnih rebotcO cissalc eht tsniaga deldnub ylthgil
"!gnihtemos gniyas s'taht dnA .saw ereht naht uoy ni evird dna leets erom tol a s'erehT .t'nevah uoy tuB"
,evres ot ytnuoc sih dah naD
,kcartecar eht morf llih eht nwod tsuJ
.nwoT selrahC nwotnwod hguorht evord dna
.ti ni doog kool uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tseb eht rof saw ti wenk htob yeht tub ,truh tI
.esirprus hcum t'nsaw taht desoppus ehS
.won ereh s'ti ,lleW" .dennirg eH
.tes nus eht sa decnad yehT ".haeY"
.eb dluow uoy detbuod ydoboN" .delkcuhc eH ".ti
.taes reh ot denruter ehs sa delims dna deggurhs tsuj ehS
.melborp ruoy s'taht sseug I tuB
.dnuora dekool neJ ".tops
"?gnos siht draeh tsrif ew nehw rebmemer uoy oD"
.enif eb d'ehS .enif eb d'eH
"?yllaer ,tub ,ti devol I
.wonk uoy ,gnidnamed si boj ehT
,kcab deppets neht
.thgil tsacrevo eht ni gnitnilg ylerab tsuj tnanetueiL tsriF a fo srab revlis ,triks htgnel-eenk dna tekcaj evilo ni
.smra sih ni reh dehsurc ylraen naD dna ,decarbme yehT
.deppots yeht dna ,dehsinif gnos tsal ehT
.boj eht morf dna ymedaca tnemecrofne wal eht morf selat htiw reh delager naD
.degnahc t'ndah taht dna ,seirots rof doog neeb syawla dah ylimaf s'naD
.sretrauq fo lufdnah a dehsif neht
gniog esuoh eht tpek d'ehs elihw pu dellac neeb dah rehtaf rieht nehw
.tey tsuj doof rof pu t'nsaw ehS
.elihw a rof gnihtemos rof gnikool neeb d'I
,reh ta dennirg eH
,irauR nosmirC ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb ”emoH gnioG“
irauR nosmirC yb
.naD ,eromyna wonk t'nod I"
.emitefil a flah ekil tlef ti tub ,mra s'yob derovaf a no slrig esoht fo eno neeb d'ehs ecnis oga gnol taht neeb t'ndah tI .delims ehS
.won thgir ,citehporp
.reh ediseb taes eht no revoc reh decalp ehS
.ylneddus kcab deppets dna
.mmhmM" .lacitpeks ylraelc saw eh
.rood eht decaf taht taes eht no flesreh delttes neJ
.htob su rof tseb s'ti sseug I tub
.noitnetta eht rof ti did eh hcum woh derednow ehS
.elbissop sa seilimaf rieht ot kcab tog nem ynam sa taht ees ot dluoc ehs tahw od ot detnaw ehs
.smailliW ytupeD ,eybdooG"
.keehc sih dekcil neJ
".ytuped a emoceb d'uoy em llet t'ndid uoY
.reh revo dehsaw cisum eht sa gnixaler
fo reh dednimer taht noitcelloc a dleh tI
.mih ot on yas ot gnitnaw neve elbuort dah syawla d'ehs dna
.wohemos deniatretne flesym peek attoG .si eruS" .reh
,notgnihsaW ot kcab reh ekat dluow tI
.won thgir ereh yats ot ydaer er'uoy kniht t'nod I tub ,uoy rof doog s'tI
.niaga elzzum reh ta deppal eH
,trohs a yb yletaidemmi tsomla deteerg saw ehs dna
.emit eritne eht hcum ytterp .H.S.A.M a ni saw I
,regnol tnemom a derats ehS ".os
.hgis a tsuj si hgis A
.tfel uoy nehw naht suoegrog erom neve er'uoY
,elbat eht no meht tup ehs sa tcejbo ot deirt naD
.rac s'retsis reh yb desuap yehT
.smra s'naD ni gnicnad wols fo sthgin gnol yltnasaelp esoht
,elbuort laer yna desuac reven eh tub ,das saw tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
!oga sraey eerht saw taht tuB .did I tahT"
.weiv niatnuom a dah ainigriV tseW ni erehwyreve tuoba tsuj ecnis ,deman yltpa saw reniD weiV niatnuoM ehT
.teerts edis gnimussanu na ffo kcab tes saw ti sa
.won sraey ruof tuoba ,hO"
.nwot ni saw ehs elihw syad wef a rof rac eht reh naol ot stnemegnarra laiceps edam dah retsis reh dna
.dah ehs naht retteb pu tpek ylraelc d'eH
.eeffoc taht htiw kcab thgir eb ll'I
tib a gnileef s'tI"
.mih ta pu dekool ehS ".haeY"
,ylerar saw hcihw ,rebos saw eh nehw yug doog a
.sih fo elzzum gib taht fo tuo gnillol eugnot sih
.rethgit elttil a reh dleh eH ".yrros
.raw eht neht dna loohcs gnisrun neewteb ,sraey xis ni emoh neeb t'nevah I
.ralupop yldliw gnieb etipsed
dna taht rof snottub desserp dna emid a ni deppord ehS
.tuo pleh ot teg I won dna
.renid eht fo wodniw eht ni noitcelfer reh ta dekool dna
,ylppa sgniht latnemadnuf ehT
,hgual a dekrab naD ".epyt
,tuo dekcab ehs sa ereht doots eH ".won ,efas evirD
.wener ot gniog er'uoY" "?taht s'tahw dnA"
.krow eht devol ev'I
.sseug I ,won rof em tsuJ"
ylteiuq delims eH ".ecno siht tsuj
.swodniw eht yb htoob a ot klaw trohs a reh del dna delkcuhc ssertiaw ehT ".uoy
.retnec eht ta dap eht dessik dna
.deggurhs ssertiaw ehT ".ylrae
,siht rebmemer tsum uoY"
.esirprus yb em thguac uoy dna ,llac enohp trohs a saw ti ,lleW"
.ti ot txen dekrap saw sgnikram ffirehS htiw drof etihw A
esoht dna ,mrofinu sih otni dewolf ruf kcalb sih yaw eht ni gnikat ,tnemom a rof mih ta derats ehS ".yawa
.naD teem ot degnarra d'ehs erehw renid eht rof ngis eht was ehs
.llihc s'retniw fo
,naD fo ngis yna ees t'ndid ehS
.wener thgim I tub ,mret ym no tfel raey rehtona evah I
"?ti si ,hguone ton s'ti tuB
.trapa deppets yllanif tub
.uoy no doog skool sihT"
.niaga renid eht yb reh koot daor eht sa mih fo espmilg tsal a thguac ehS
.txen od d'eh tahw tuoba gnisseug seituped eht tpek syawla saw eh dna
?uoy tuoba tahW" ".haeY" .dehgis ehS ".tsom
.esnopser ni elzzum sih dekcil dna delims ehS
,stnerap reh ees ot neeb ydaerla d'ehS
.ylrae saw ehs taht tsuj saw ti ebyam rO
.sklof tisiv ot evael ym fo emos ni gnihsac m'I ,revo raw eht htiW"
"?swonk ohw os ,elihw a ni mih nees t'nevah I
.gnidnamed s'boj eht
.desuap dna rac reh ot rood eht denepo ehS ".od I"
.elttil a demriuqs ehS ".serusaem
.pu dellup ehs sa serit eht rednu dehcnurc levarG
wap s'naD denepo neJ ".uoy
.eb t'ndluow uoy ,ereh yppah m'I
,yats t'nac I tuB
.slraeP fo gnirtS
.tnemom a rof ecnelis ni decnad yeht dna
;ytuped a sa llew mih devres evah tsum taht reh ta kool a delevel naD
.desirprus ton m'I"
.dnim reh degnahc ehs erofeb og ot detnaw ehs dna
dniheb deggaw liat s'eiggaM ".taerg
.oot ,sgnos rewen erew erehT
.wap sih fo kcab eht revo ylthgil bmuht reh debbur neJ ".seog
"?ereh kcab uoy sgnirb tahW"
,ti raeh ot detnaw t'ndah rehtom reH
.seireviled gnikam srevird wef a dna sdnarre gninnur seviw yltsom saw ciffart eht
pets reh ni yaws artxe elttil a htiw taes reh ot kcab deklaw ehS
”emoH gnioG“:yojne esaelP
.loohcs hgih retfa thgir tfel d'ehs ecnis emoh raen erehwyna evael tsrif reh no saw ehs
,elsia s'renid ytpme eht ni doots yeht sa
.ylmrif mih dessik dna naD tsniaga flesreh desserp ehS
.rennid ecin a ekiM dna ecilA ewo d'ehs ,kcab tog ehs nehW
,ni deklaw ehs nehw xobekuj a deips d'ehS
.nrut wols a hguorht dekcor yehT ".did
,ti rof nrut eht ssim ylraen did ehS
.cisum rieht rof ssendnof taerg a dettimda ehs dna ,senorepahc eht desaelp dah relliM nnelG dna stopS knI ehT .efas yltsom
,ledom s'raey tsal neeb evah thgim tI
niaga dennirg ehS ".ti ekil I
.yadot uoy fo erac gnikat eb ll'I .eiggaM s'eman yM"
.gnikniht er'uoy tahw sseug a evah I
;yldnof hsad eht dettap neJ
.neJ ,degnahc ev'uoY
".emoh llits saw siht ebyam fi ees ot detnaw I
,ylimaf reh morf draeh ydaerla t'ndah eh tahw derahs ehS
.emoh ruoy neeb syawla s'ti ,neJ"
.dlohserht eht dessorc ehs
.elzzum reh kcil ot elbat eht revo denael dna delkcuhc eH
.niaga delkcuhc neJ
"?ytuped a neeb uoy evah gnol woh dnA"
,telorvehC dlo s'naD ees t'ndid ehs tub ,tnorf tuo srac wef a erew erehT
,ssik erom eno rof ni denael ehS
,rennid yrotarbelec a spahreP
,edisni tnew dna flesreh gnirimda fo hguone dah ehS
dluoc ehS .reh ta delims eH ".yppah kool uoY
.taes eht no depmuht liat reH ".yppaH
.spil sih ta dekcil dna delims neJ ".elttil
ffo oidar eht denrut ehS
;teiuq ylriaf saw ti ,noonretfa etal A
.elbirret elttil a syawla erew uoY
.ypoc a nettog yllanif
,dekcap-maj er'ew ,ees nac uoy sa ,lleW"
,secnad loohcs hgih morf derebmemer ehs sgnos esoht rof snottub eht dehsup neht ,tnemom a rof ti deredisnoc ehS
.hcamots reh ni gniworg neeb dah taht gnileef gniknis eht ot noitnetta reh dellac snoitavresbo s'naD "?gnorw s'tahW
.seog ti woh ees dna siht yrt d'I derugif neht ,sraey elpuoc a rof loohcs retfa tuoba dekconk I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
!neJ yeH" .keehc reh dekcil dna dennirg eH .pu tel eh dna
.srettel ni meht htiw pu peek ot deganam d'ehs
,sraey xis gnol A  .sraey xis tuobA
"?uoy gnihctaw ni tsol tsuj t'nsaw I syas tahW"
hguoht ,pu hctac ot doog dna ,meht ees ot doog neeb dah tI
.tuo reh dewollof neht
"!lacipyt ,yawa tnew I retfa thgiR
.yltcefrep mrofinu ytuped s'ffirehs kcalb sih tif ot demees eh dna
.wonk dluow lrig a kniht d'uoY"
.slrig rehto neeb ev'ereht ylerus tuB
"!gnitiaw fo derit tog I"
:thgir neeb dah naD tub ,yawa saw ehs elihw ni enog evah tsum tI
.oot ,uoy dessim ev'I ,naD ,hO"
.mirb eht deppit dna tah sih ot wap a desiar eH ".smailliW
.reverof neeb s'ti ekil sleef tI .uoy dnA"
,mra reh rednu kcab ti dekcut dna revoc reh derehtag ehS
.won esrow eb thgim uoy kniht I" .dennirg eH ".elbirret
.elbat eht ssorca denael eh sa dekrep srae siH "?llitS"
,edarg hthgiE .esruoc fO"
'.eid em tel t'nod esaelp' ',mra ym evas
,erugif gnihctef rehtar a tuc ehs thguoht ehS
.yaw reh dekool eh sa devaw dna doots ehS
.dnuora dekool dna desuap neJ
;esrun a emoceb ot reh nevird dah tahw saw tahT
.lleps eht kaerb ot flesreh koohs ehS .emit gnol a
.yawa gniog s'ti kniht t'nod I .sknahT"
,ereh ti devol syawla ev'I wonk uoY .ma I"
.mrofinu knip-yllufniap tsomla na ni ssertiaw derruf-etihw
htob meht til tesnus ehT
.mrofinu eht was I litnu ti eveileb etiuq t'ndid tsuj I tub ,em dlot eH
.uoy dessim ev'I .ereh m'I dnA
.neJ ,oot ,uoy evol I"
.ti dessim evah t'ndluoc yllaer ehs
.tuo emoc tsuj dah acnalbasaC
".taht tuobA .haeY" .dehgis ehS
,mrofinu reh dehtooms dna rac eht fo tuo tog neJ
.nac I nehw yb pots ot yrt ll'I tub ,pu lluf er'ew ,ees nac uoy sA
srae reh neewteb revoc ecivres reh delttes ehS
,sniloiv eht neht
.haeY" ".yzarc og d'I