ehS	         ”.eF aveuN morf lla er’ew ,kroY weN morf ton er’ew tpecxE
”,neetxiS teg syug dna neetneveS teg slrig
.did I naht eybdooG tuoba erom wenk eninac eht
,sedaced rof yretsym eht evlos ot gniyrt neeb dah
ahtnamaS	         .sgniht ruo gnikcapnu ot kcab tnew neht ,deggurhs ,skool derahs I dna
.teerts daed eht gnola dekrap srac wef a eb ot dekool tahw fo espmilg a thguac
lateleks dna erabdaerht
.noitagitsevni s’thginot rof ton ,tsael tA
.boj yad reh edistuo ffuts gniod dekil ssenoil niatnuom eht ,ylniaM
,eniltleb eht fo htuos erehwemos saw
,lleW“ .citpekS .rM gnilaever tuohtiw lartuen niamer ot tseb sih gniod ylbisiv
.5591 yb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
A	         ”.eno thguorb ew erus gnikam redisnoc ton ot trams oot s’ehS .eno thguorb ehs ,esruoc fO“ .detats eh
,snoisrev ralimis dna euqinu nwo rieht evah selpoep dna serutluc rehtO
rednetrab eht miJ ot kcab su morf tnew seye siH
,ruoh na ot setunim
.edistuo gnidarap stsohg gnilwoh fo mrots tsud citoahc
citpekS .rM ot revo despmilg I
.flesti eybdooG fo etats eht nevig yllaicepse
,deunitnoc lerriuqs eht dna ,reh no llef seye ruo fo eerht lla nehw yawa dekool ehs
,ydob a ekil saw ocixeM weN ,eybdooG              2 fo
.troffe eht etaicerppa ro erac ot knurd oot
.mih ot aremac eht detcerid ehs nehw ahtnamaS ot delims neht ,dehgis
ruoy sa gnidnatsrednu sa t’nsi boj yad ym ta ssob yM“
.VT eht dniheb morf detarbiv kconk duol
rekrad tlef moor eht ,ylnedduS
?noitcif lla ro tcaf lla ti sI
.naem I ,lausu nahT“
,syek yrevlis etarapes ruof decudorp dah ehs ,kcab emac ehs nehW
flow dega-elddim a saw rekaeps eht taht ees ot enal eht nwod denrut em dna eiruaL
,gnihtolc laitini ruo erow llits I dna ehS	           ”!nekat tnioP“
.em dniheb gnilffuhs draeh I sa niaga delggig hcolB .srM hcihw ot ,deksa I
neerg noen reh dna tekcaj etihw yM
nwonknu eht tsniaga ffo ecaf lliw
”?won od ew od tahw...oS“
d’I“	         ”—sterces erahs ,seirots
retteB“	           ”?!sduolc tsud ’nikcuf
tsrif eht no tneve larutanrepus emas siht dessentiw flesmih reppepluC leinaD ,dnegel nabru ot gnidroccA“
.noitpecxe on era saciremA eht dna
”!tirips eht
.eloC gniK dlo n’rehcir eb d’I ,tihs taht em deksa ohw enoyreve rof kcub a dah I fI“ ,deffocs flow dega-elddim emas ehT
regoR“	         	         ”.enif uoy raeh nac I .der no slevel eht gnidnes er’uoY .scim eht otni ylduol oot klat t’nod uoy erus ekam ,eiruaL dnA
klawedis eht no llits er’eW“
ohw ro ,tahw ,yhw ,woh wenk ydoboN
.si ti sa hguone yrrulb deef eht gnikam s’tI .daeh ruoy don t’nod esaelp ,marB“
.su tuoba lla gnilriws dniw yrd eht htiw gnihctiwt ,annetna na ekil
.pirt ruo no gnirb ot thguoht slammam lla fo ahtnamaS taht selggog dnas krad emos dna sdaeh ruo gnirevoc seidooh fo riap a sulp
woH“	         .ffocs elpmis a htiw em derewsna ohw ,naeD deksa I
”...sraey eht revo dlot evah stnediser remrof taht seirots eht era snwot tsohg rehto eht morf eybdooG setarapes tahw ,revewoH
toN“	          .yaw ruo gnimoc sduolc krad eht deyevrus oot ehs sa delbmurg eiruaL
sgnidnal noom ollopA eht taht kcaba nekat saw
”,taht rof kcuf
,letoM rewolF treseD eht edisni thgir
.yllausac ekops I
aera hctorc eht raen erehwon tub
.ylevitruf gnihctiwt dna gniltsirb tuons gniyarg sih no sreksihw eht ,niaga kcab dna
.wap dereffo reh gnikahs ,hgual elbatrofmoc a dekaf dna
.seceiprae eht fo dne rehto eht no remlac dna laivoj erom dednuos eciov s’ahtnamaS ”,raelc dna
.ti tuoba yssalc enola tel
,niar emos teg annog er’ew syas osla tI“ .detroter I
,nwot ni efil tuoba uoy ksa ew nac
,rehtaf dna rehtom reh htiw pihsnoitaler s’ahtnamaS otni hcum oot yrp t’ndid I
,ecalp siht tuoba swonk ydaerla aciremA ni snoitacol lamronarap ro 66 etuoR htiw dessesbo
”?won ylrae os pu teg ot su fo diputs saw ti knihT“
niarb eht dna ,revil ,sgnul eht ,flah reppu eht deniatnoc htron sti
,semoh nabrubus denodnaba fo snezod eb dluow ereht ,htuos gnidniW
”,siht naht reggib saw loohcs hgih morf mooremoh
”!no s’ti ,marB...dna ,owt...eerht...ruoF“
.llah eht fo dne eht ta nwod ,71 dna 61 smooR
.ega morf tuo nrow nialp tsuj ro
”,ti ekil t’now
.od ot krow dah I dna gnag ehT
.wap thgir ym desiar dna ria eht dehcnup I
enola tel ,snoitagitsevni lamronarap eseht no su nioj reh tel ot meht ecnivnoc ot deganam ehs woH
er’eW“ .redrob nanozirA eht sdrawot
,epacsdnal larotsap sseldne ylgnimees dna
”?ew llahs ,scisab eht revo og s’tel
”.htnom tsal semit eerht krow ot ni dellac ydaerla ev’I“
”,ma’am ,yats su gnittel rof sknahT“	         .delward ahtnamaS
,moob ot ymonoce lacol sti desuac eybdooG
.aremac reh derewol ahtnamaS
.snaej ym otni syek eht detekcop dna pu meht dehctans I ”!gniht eruS“	         ”.esaelp ,eseht esol ot ton yrT
,eiteewS“	         ”?su fo draeh reven d’uoy nokcer I“
.ocixeM weN ,eybdooG kcurts yllanif mrots tsud taht sa
.neht ti tuoba maS ot klat ll’eW“
.tnempiuqe dna sesactius emos gniyrrac ,edisni yaw rieht no erew eiruaL dna ,ahtnamaS ,naeD
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
,sessalg delkcepseb ni lerriuqs desserd ylevitavresnoc a dna ,eidooh deppiznu na gniraew ssenoil niatnuom a
”?tsal dluow ti yas ti did gnol
.revetahw ,erus tuB
.llor n‘ kcor tratspu eht htiw erutluc eht no ecnanimod rof deiv zzaj dekaos-nig dna ,skcub ruof naht ssel rof dah eb dluoc laem esruoc-eerht lluf a
.derednow I ,hturt eht reh llet eh dluow nehW
”.thginot emoc ot thgin gnorw eht dekcip ay knihT“   .dedihc I ”?yawa su evag tahW“   .su deksa eh
.anemonehp larutanrepus fo retnec eht neeb sah eybdooG ,gnidnuof sti sa kcab raf sa gniog
nwo reh gniwollof sdneirf deniamer ew retfa rotagitsevni dael-oc ym sa
”,marB ,sknird ygrene eerht dna peels fo sruoh ruof no evivrus nac su fo lla
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
litnu…worg dna worg ot detrats ti ,etuor eht ssorca ytic dna nwot rehto yreve ekiL
.delggiw liat tibbar yM
.em dniheb rood tnorf eht ot debmuht I sa elims gnimrahc a evag I
ahtnamaS	         .demihc eiruaL
niaga gniraeppasid erofeb devaw hcolB .srM ”!sdik ,oot
”,evif litnu no og d’ti dias uoy thguoht
,liaj ytnuoc eht ta llec nosirp egareva na naht reggib on gnieb moor eht etipseD
.ahtnamaS dna eiruaL ot stxet tnes dna
.sdeb niwt s’naeD dna
.gnidnuof s’nwot eht fo neewollaH
”?neewollaH naht emit retteb
.flesti etuoR eht gnihcaorppa tsaf
.yks thgin eht ssorca gnimaor stirips dna stsohg fo noissecorp a no desucof
,yaw ruo denrut skcab dehcnuh lareves ,thgin tahT
dna egnuoL odaroD lE dellac etuoR eht gnola rab lacol a fo ngis noen elbazingocer eht tops dluoc I
.eybdooG ni erew ew yhw t’nsaw taht tub
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb ”ocixeM weN ,eybdooG“
.nwonknu sgniht tuoba ytisoiruc ym derahs oot ehs wonk ydaerla em depleh tsap eht ni stifeneb-htiw-dneirf lanoisacco na gnieB
,noitats sag s’ylimaf sih gnisitrevda trihs-t a dna snaej nrot ni desserd flow nacixeM
.thgis ni gnihtyreve gniteknalb tresed fo reyal esned a yb derucsbo thgiliwt neewollaH mid eht tsniaga dehsalc
maet sih dna eh ,swonk marB sa raf sa
.esiwrehto redisnoc ot meht rof nosaer a etaerc ot saw detnaw I gniht tsal ehT
.teertS niaM no spohs derettuhs fo taes a dima
.gniteprac yawllah denrettap eht denaelc slacimehc revetahw dna
”?slaG ?syug ,dnuos taht s’woH .egatoof eht fo tser eht teg ot worromot gninrom eht ni ylrae-artxe pu teg nac eW
riaF“	         ”.sesu ecalp siht revetahw ro ,syek ro
:66 etuoR yb detcesib dna
tceffe citamard rof yltrap ,desuap I
ta ffo gnippot setamitse susnec htiw
,degamad-retaw ,depraw meht fo emos ,sdrac ssenisub
,gnikcilc dna gnipyt deunitnoc
,snevaeh eht ot ’anaciremA egatniv‘ demaercs llits esle gnihtyreve
eht dekohc setteragic tuo tnrub
yks eht otni pu
,lleW“	         .noitcerid ym ni elzzum sih dekrej flow nacixeM eht
eninac ehT .ylper on teg ot ylno ,deksa eH
,ti pota gnignuol htimS doowtruK dnif
.taes regnessap eht morf gnipacse retfa sbmil ym gnihcterts detrats I
,sesactius ym barg ot ahtnamaS tsap deppets
saw taht noitacol emirp eht ,metsys yawhgih rojam elgnis a yb detcennoc won erew ainrofilaC dna tsewdiM naciremA eht sA
rotagitsevni lamronarap dna cihcysp tnec-owt yreve rof rallod a dah I fi
,retcarahc nootrac a ekil gniliec retsalp eht hguorht dna otni thgir gnipmuj
”?ekil eht dna deretnuocne ev’uoy sgniht tahw
”,stnuh dliw fo cipot eht no desucof eb ot gniog er’ew ,thgiN neewollaH siht roF“
,dedda dna ,eson sih gnilknirw
yM“	         .did lla ew tnemeticxe emas eht derahs eh llet dluoc I ,liat eninac sih ni gaw detapicitna eht morf tub ,moor ruo kcolnu ot dereetnulov ylsseldrow rekrowoc yM
,moor gnirobhgien eht ot nwod teef lareves deklaw ahtnamaS dna eiruaL	         ”!ot deen ew fi pan neve spahrep ,ni delttes teg s’tel woN
”?ti ta er’ew elihw oot uoy drocer ew naC“
ni er’uoY“ .niahcyek 66 etuoR yrebbur a gnissessop eno hcae
naeD llet ot em detnaw ahtnamaS dnA“
.gnimit htiw boj retteb a od dluow dniw nmad siht hsiw tsuj I“
.smra dessorc htiw denoitnem naeD ”,hguoht apap
.nav desu eht fo tuo deppets
.wonk reven dluow I ,rebmem a sa yteicoS sretnuH lamronaraP eht nioj
,naelc ylgnisirprus sa tuo doots ybbol s’ratS treseD eht ,swodniw detnit eht dnoyeb tub
,drow s’renwo eht ot eurT
,seires yrots naipotsyd yrruf gniogno sih sa hcus seirots rehto dnif osla nac uoy erehw ,noertaP sih no ,htnoM tumS retsnoM
,yrotcidartnoc era seinomitset eseht fo emos hguoht
,repapswen tcnufed rieht ni detroper neeb s’taht esac tsiegretlop demrifnoc eno tsael ta ,sgnithgis tsohg dradnats eht s’erehT
.stsohg dna skcitsmoorb dna ,sehctiw dna snilboG :wonk uoY .neewollaH
oS“	         ”!em ekil deticxe eb dluohs uoY !ereh yllanif
,hctauqsaS yradnegel eht yb kcatta na gnivivrus detnuocer enO
”?miJ ,uoy tuoba tahW
s’tI“ .delkcuhc I ”,yllaer toN“
”.thgin rehtona ereh yats t’nac eW
.ni yats ot su rof letom dlo na detarepo stnediser gniniamer os ro derdnuh eseht fo eno
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sthgilhsalf ruo ,senohp ruo
.lla ta gnirrucco gniht a hcus fo ecnedive rehtag ot elba neeb sah ydobon dna
,reh weivretni su gnivah ot nepo eb dluow ehs fi reh ksa dluoc I erofeB
t’nia uoY“ .daeh sih fo edisni eht morf sgnaf gnissim wef a deciton I dna ,nirg yldneirf a dereffo dna deddon eH .sllarevo dehctap dna tuo nrow gniraew raeb ylzzirg gniyarg a saw ti gnidnet nam eht erehw
”!naeD ,enif did uoY“
”?tahw roF“	         ”.’uoy knaht‘
.renroc eht ni afos deretslohpu eht no atseis a ekat
”,evird ot reetnulov t’ndid ohw yug eht syas
.tuo detniop naeD
.reh dniheb gniltsirb liat reh ,pu ekops ahtnamaS
sreweiv erutuf eht deteerg I
”?saremac esoht erA“
!emoclew er’uoY“ .rehtegot swap ym
.retnuoc eht rednu tlenk dna ,deilper ehs
.edisni deppets eh nehw deppiuq naeD
I	           ”!edir eht rof gnola tsuj m’I !siht od ot detnaw ohw eno eht er’uoY“ .dekrans ehs ”?taht od annaw I dluow kcuf
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.ton dah segavar sti ,deppots dah emit fo scitehtsea eht fi tuB
,ecnartne eht ot dna 66 etuoR dekcarc eht ssorca dehsur yletaidemmi eiruaL dna eM
.taorht ym deraelc I litnu rewsna t’ndid yehT
.naeD dna em htiw moor a erahs annaw lla’y sselnU“
,niaga attocarret dlo doog hcuot ot taerg tlef tI
:edaced rof srehcraeser lamronarap deracs dna
,saremac evisnepxe ruo fo eno spahrep ro
,taorht sih deraelc flow nacixeM ehT
sessenisub gnilggurts fo elpuoc a dna
,swollof nwot eht
I	         .llew sa ti no peels ot detnaw I dna ,sih fo eciov gnipsar ,yllasan taht ni ’ssabmud‘ a enoemos llac ot gnitiaw
”ocixeM weN ,eybdooG“
,tuoyal dna ezis s’71 mooR ta tnemezama emas eht deciov slrig eht ,ylralimiS	         .detsej naeD
,swodniw nward s’moor eht ot gninrut erofeb
,noissimrep ruoy htiw dna ,eybdooG fo seiretsym eht otni gnikool
dna dniw ,dnas t’nsi taht 66 fo trap a ot devom evah ew t’ndluoc yhW“ .denaomeb I ”?ocixeM weN ot og ot evah ylimaf ym did yhW“	           ***   .gnieerga erofeb
,thgis ni luos a ton llitS
!edud ,su gnipleh fo tuo gnitteg er’uoy kniht t’noD“
,lla fo dnoceS“ ,dias I ,nehT ”.kcuF“
s’tahT“	         ”.nwot otni og yllautca ew nehw deticxe eb ll’I“
laes retaw dega fo ffihw a htiw dexim ,renehserf ria na fo stnecs eht delahni I sa em dniheb delggiw liat yM
em neewteb ecaps worran eht ni gnidnats aiomena fo elgnit a tlef llits I
”,ecalp s’dad ym ta kcis ni llac dluoc I“
,dias dna taorht ym deraelc I
.ecneirepxe larutanrepus
,)nirgahc sih ot hcum ,citpekS .rM mih gnillac devol I(
.sretsubtsohG laer eht
,9691 ,ht81 yluJ ,yadirF no peelsa llef stnediser nehw
.ti gnola serutcurts ro sesuoh on htiw daor levarg fo hctap ynit a—
citehtsea egatniv eht decarbme erutcurts ehT
eht fo traeh eht ni deltsen
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,gnitseggus em ot del ssendlob fo kceps a dna spil ym fo lruc yrw A
,peY   .snortap eht morf slwocs wef a ees ot pu kool ot deen t’ndid I
.tellaw ym rof dehsif I sa
”.sllaw eht hguorht uoy raeh nac eW“
.derettum ehs ”,sknahT“
,nekops-tfos a derettu I .enohp ym ta emit erom eno decnalg sa seye ym dellor I
.deb tsesolc eht tsniaga gninael ,denaorg eh
uoy tel I did yhw ,noitseuq
,rotceted FME eht gnildarc lerriuqs yhs eht gnihctac ylbissop yad eno tuoba dekoj netfo I .nerdlihc ekil ti deroda tub tnempiuqe .S.H.P eht rof erac tsuj t’ndid rebmem maet yvvas-hcet ruO
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.tekcaj gnitsud yvaeh a ni
,retsiger sih ediseb gnittis raj pit eht ot neht
gnilevram ro snoitaroced neewollaH ykcat wef a ta seye ym gnillor sediseB
.tneinevnoc erom dna retsaf levart edam metsyS yawhgiH etatsretnI wen eht ecnis
.ecnartne tnorf s’letom eht fo swodniw eht detluassa dnas fo tsug gnorts a sa thgir werc ym fo tser eht htiw gnola dnuora denrut I	         ”!ym hO“
”.stsoh rieht fo lla htiw skcolraw fo snevoC
?stops emos erolpxe ebyam dna ,egatoof emos rehtag ,tuo og nac eiruaL dna eM“
,seye ym dellor dna dehgual
,moorhtab desolc s’moor eht yb gnidnats
tsomlA	         ”!letoM ratS treseD eht ot emocleW
,desimorp ew dna ,su deksa uoY“
yteicoS sretnuH lamronaraP eht denioj eiruaL
ytpme dna sriahc ytpme eht fo tfel raf eht no
dniw mrawekul eht hguorht egatoof war demlif ti sa sdooh ruo fo tuo dekeep orPoG A
weF“	         ”.tnempiuqe eht edisni dnas yna teg dna tuo og ot su tnaw t’nod I“
,rucco ot espal emit eht desuac
”,dnammoC ,taht
hguoht ,srehto ot gniklat elbuort dah
su teg uoy nac ,yaw eht yB“
fitom cirolklof a si ’tnuH dliW‘ eht ,wonk t’nod ohw esoht roF“
.körangaR gnirud dleifelttab eht ssorca sgnikiV dna sreidlos fo ymra na dael dluow flesmih nidO taht dias saw ti nehw
.devil-trohs saw modeerf siht morf tlef I noitale yna tub
.repapllaw eht hguorht deirrac eciov s’eiruaL
erusopmoc niager ot deirt I
emaS“	         ”.elpoep gnikcuf lla fo uoy htiw moor letom a ni tis ot tsuj evird ruoh-ruof a erudne t’ndid osla I“
.deneppah ydaerla
”,66 etuoR dehcnual tnemnrevog .S.U eht retfa raey a revo eybdooG dehsilbatse reppepluC .T leinaD nehw ,7291 ni kcab yaw eht lla snigeb yrots ehT“
”,nuh ,sartxe emos evah nac uoy esruoc fo tub ,sdrac esu t’nod eW“ ”.wonk uoy ,tuo ro ni dekcol teg t’nod ew os tsuJ ?smoor eht rof sdrac yek artxe emos
.acilper skwahthgiN eht ot txen thgir
,stleb ruo ot depparts soidar
.su dniheb rood eht gnisolc erofeb enot ni deerga I
suoirav ni eot ot daeh dekced saw ecnartne tnorf eht ot detcennoc yawhcra ehT
tsohg llet ,sgab gnipeels eht htaen‘ eldduc lla nac eW
,deffuh I ”,elohssa ,ereh
.lavirra ruo democlew
,ereh nwod og ot detnaw nwotrekaL ro sallertsE saL morf naciremA tneitapmi on
lleT“	         .moorhtab ynit eht ediseb skwahthgiN fo acilper demarf eht
,mra dehctertstuo na htiw denway naeD
a sseug I dna ,uoy rof yek a ,uoy rof yek A“ .syek moor fo sriap owt eht tuo dellup dna sesactius ym nwod tes
.edisni dehsur ehs sa gnilkcac
dnA“	         .ecnartne tnorf eht sdrawot pu dednuob I sa ”!lliw I dnA“
egats ynit a dah neve odaroD lE ehT
.eybdooG hguorht welf dna dekcolf ohw sremooB ybaB gnigrus eht ot sknaht llA
”,letom yrutnec-dim a yletinifed si
.rehtruf tnedicni dias ssucsid t’ndid eH
.meetse-fles reh detceffa ylereves ti wonk did I tub
.krims yrw a htiw em ot meht dednah neht
ngis yalpsid noen a htiw tsap eht morf tsalb siht detelpmoc letoM ratS treseD ehT
”,aretecte ,gninoitidnoc ria ,sVT ,gnibmulp retteb ekil seitinema nredom tog ew tub ,era
.hguoht noitatpmet eht derongi
ot detpmet tlef tsomla I
,ylnedduS .eno dlo eht decalper metsys yawhgih wen a
,su dniheb noziroh krad eht no tuo gnikool elihw niaga deksa I
”?morf taht teg uoy d’erehW“
”?miJ ,sdaeh rieht no s’yekcihood meht tog yeht od yhW“ ”.dreN“
ehT“	           ”.eiruaL ,raf oot rednaw t’noD
uoY“	         ”!thgin doog a evaH“
,gniteprac puos aep ylgu eht ta eson ym gnilknirw sa llew sa ,gniliec eht no pmal ssalg-deniats eht ta
.ni degdol erew naeD dna em erehw 61 mooR hctam ot dah wenk I hcihw
,stigid-elbuod eht ni deyats stsoc enilosag nehw emit a ,are enogyb a fo
,moor eht otni ria looc fo stsug desluvnoc
I“	         ”.thgindim retfa lit‘ gniog peek ot desoppus s’edistuo mrots tsud nmad taht syas ti dna ,niaga rehtaew eht dekcehc tsuj I ,yawynA .tcaf ni
,llitS	         .hcum sa eye-ot-eye ees t’ndid ew emahS
”,oot uoy kcuf ,ffo
!ocixeM weN ,eybdooG
,ygolohtym esroN ot kcab yaw eht lla setad sihT
stnediser dnasuoht-eerht tsael ta revo
.dedeen snoitacol no noitamrofni larutluc dna ,larutanarap ,cirolklof ,cirotsih rehtag su depleh eH .maet eht rof rehcraeser tnegilid a sa tub
.setunim elpuoc a rof detiaw dna ecno lleb eht gnar I ,ksed tnorf eht sdrawot teef wef a egaggul ym gniyrraC
;reppiz ym gniodnu no desucof seye ym tpek I
,’dnekeeW tsoL s’eybdooG‘ sa ti ot derrefer netfo stsiroeht ycaripsnoC
.su dniheb gnihtemos ot denediw seye s’nexiv dega-elddim eht
stifsim fo maet gatgar ruo ,sboj ruo did ew sa gnol os
,ylno thgin eno roF
”.seog ti woh wonk uoY
.neercsffo deddon eH
.emoh nabrubus s0791 a fo moor gnivil eht morf thgir nekat tlef tI
srehcraeser yroeht ycaripsnoc dna lamronarap fo ytnelP
,su dnuora no gniog gnihtyreve
enoynA“ .htaerb ym hctac ot osla tub
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
elor latovip a yalp did eh ,swal-ni rettib ekil thguof netfo ew sa hcum sa ,naeD rof sA
citpeks tnediser ruo sa ylno toN
,dias ehs ”,ton ma I
”?msaisuhtne eht s’erehw
dna sotohp htiw mirb eht ot dellif rodirroc llams a nwod detfird tI
.regnif a htiw eceip eht deppat I
eiruaL	         ”.ni su kcehc og ll’I“
cisum evawropav ot gninetsil emit eerf sih sdneps ohw
?neht eybdooG fo sneve dna sddo eht fo emos tnemucod ot ereh er’uoy nokcer I“
,erots yrecorg nepo enol eht
dekrep srae ym ,nav eht fo tuo tog I tnemom eht dna
.su euS .stsiruot erew ew
”,syeK eht ot eriter ot seinnep hguone evah ylbaborp d’I
eruS“	         ”?oga sraey ytxis erew yeht sa emas eht smoor eht era ,em llet ,oS“
gniogno na htiw neewollaH gnitarbelec &
.ecneidua evil a fo tnorf ni gig tsrif rieht rof ni gniyalp fo demaerd sdnab eganeet tsom rab evid yhcteks fo tros eht saw ti tub ,drow eht fo noitpircsed yreve ni evid a saw tI
ot steknalb nottoc fo elip a htaeneb semarf gnikaerc eht morf
”?ronoh eht tnaw uoy od ,naeD“
,ecneidua eht demrofni naeD
,repeels thgil a m’I .t’nod I on
”?emoc ot em ecnivnoc
.drawnwod dedlof srae ym fo enO
,doG ot tsenoH
.tesolc renroc eht ni sesactius ruo decalp eh sa
,sega ni nees d’ehs lammam tsrif eht neeb d’I fi sa wap reh dehsiws ,taeh ocixeM weN eht etipsed trihs-t dialp a erow ehS
nwot tsohg suomafni
.noci 66 etuoR a yb deppot daor eht gnola
,ereh gniyats neeb s’taht sretsubtsohG laer eht er’yeht gnidneterp
”,srebmem ffats gnissarah yllauxes si ssob eht taht RH mrofni ot ekil
,sdrac artxe emos su teg ot tegrof t’noddnA
,yawa selim lareves demees sduolc tsud
marB“	         .namowselas yldneirf a ekil delims tey
”,neewollaH“ .deksa eiruaL
dluoW .mih ot denrut kcab ym htiw drib eht deppilf I hcihw ot
.ti rof suoregnad erom
,nedlog gnihton saw ereht ,egnuoL odaroD lE eht deman gnieb roF
I	         ”?syek eht ,yaw eht yb dnA“
tahW“	         ”?ssel on ,neewollaH no dnA
ehT	         ?dribrednuhT ni tnedicni pukooh eht revo teg reve eh
.rehto eht ot morf dekool seye s’enoyrevE .deksa naeD
”,gnihton meht evig ew fi sreweiv ruo lliw rehtieN“	         .denoitnem I
ot denutta era sesnes ruo taht si tibbarkcaj a tuoba gniht enO
,hsilgnE ni gniyas erofeb hsinapS ni gnihtemos gnirettum eninac llat eht
”,regnol… nwot fo tuo gniyats rof em ta yrgna teg ot stnerap ym tnaw t’nod I dnA“
.sregnarts rehto htiw did ehs sa su htiw yldab sa ton
dna reeb dellips ,elats fo ycnegnup yvaeh eht elihw ,ecnartne ruo til gnithgil noen miD
,rotceted ecroF evitomortcelE s’taht—
.deneppah tahw fo noitcellocer on yllautriv htiw
.rotagitsevni dael s’yteicoS eht sa did I naht ylsuoires erom tsomla naicinhcet s’yteicoS eht sa boj latovip reh koot ehs ,niaga nehT .buc nrobwen lautca na ekil
,’yadnuS nettogroF dna yadrutaS gnissiM eht‘ ro
pu evig tsuj ot tuoba saw I dna
ahtnamaS“	         ”?egatoof emos teg dna tuo og llits nac ew kniht uoy oD“
dworc elitsoh a ot tuo stug rieht gniyalp
duoL“	           ”?lrig ,ereht llits uoy
,evE s’wollaH llA yreve tsomla dniw eht ni gniliaw yltsohg gniraeh tuoba deklat evah sessentiw emoS
,oS“	         .renroc eht dnuora
sihT“	         ”.hguoht mooremoh ym ekil sllems yletinifeD“
.derewsna nexiv eht ”,ekat ro evig
”,taerG“	         ”!drah tih yeht ,tih yeht nehW“
.thgin eht evivrus nac yeht rehtehw dna
.daeha hcraes gnol a eb t’ndluow yllufepoh tahw rof dedeen ew gnihtyrevE	           .tekcop ym ni—
,llah nwot eht sa nwonk esiwrehto ,gniog ydob a speek taht lativ gnihtyreve—
,sicoV sumoD yb
tinu gninoitidnoc ria nredom a
,god.ecioveht ta
,delahxe dna delahni naeD
”,thgindim lit‘ no og ll’ti dediced ylneddus ppa rehtaew eht
1 traP ,sicoV sumoD yb )ocixeM weN ,eybdooG“    -flesti sllac taht
I“	         ”…rehtie sklof etats-fo-tuo eht no detrats em teg neve t’noD“ .uv àjéD
.yteicoS sretnuH lamronaraP eht ni
s’moor letom eht ni esop deticxe na otni dexaler neht deneffits erutsop yM
,sOFU ,sdnuohlleH nees evah ot mialc ohw sessentiw s’ereht neht tuB
.ytrevop nwo rieht ot lleweraf yas dluow snezitic sih dna reppepluC
”.ereht elttil a no dna no delbmar I deirrow elttil a m’I“
”.yteicoS sretnuH lamronaraP eht er’eW .sdneirf ym dna em rof smoor fo elpuoc a dekoob I“
A	         ”!semoc mrots eht erofeb ni kcehc retteb ew ,gnag ,nom’C“
.niaga gnikrow detrats traeh ym ecno delahxe I ”,ffilchtaeH
detanicsaf s’taht
.eciwt ti tih I ,tnemgdelwonkca oN
!uoy teem ot erusaelp ,hcolB amroN“
.llew hsulb sih edih ot deganam eninac eht ”,saicarG“   ”!naeD ,ereht taerg did uoY“
ni denut stnediser emit eht yb tub
,renroc s’potretnuoc eht ni dekcut retupmoc ot tnew ehs dna ,desiar sworbeye s’nexiv eht nehW
,nom’C“	         .tnempiuqe ruo ,sulP .kcab eht morf egaggul s’enoyreve tuo gnillup detrats ehs sa delggig ahtnamaS elihw ,seciov rieht ni tnemyojne eht dengief eiruaL dna naeD ,ylevitcepseR
.tsap eht ot dna erutuf eht ot delevart ev’yeht mialc ohw elpoep erom emos ,slegna ,snomed
deksa naeD ”,erons ton od uoy em
.dekrep srae ,detseggus I
.etuor suomaf eht ees llits ot hguone esolc tub
”,tihS“	         ”.sallerbmu gnirb ot trams erew ew tsael ta os
,ylikcuL	         .ytilaer a gnieb sa enigami ot elbissopmi tsomla saw ti taht
.ppuR oJ arbeD ekil hguone ylegnarts delggig neht ,dehgis ehs
,stneve larutanrepus s’eybdooG hguorht devil ohw esoht fo secneirepxe eht tuoba nrael eiruaL dna marB tahw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,rab eht ot pu deldis eW
”!tuc dnA“   ”!tuo dnif s’teL
,ydob a ekil saw ocixeM weN ,eybdooG
.ytilauq ria
eybdooG fo tnediser yreve erehw deneppah tnedicni suomafni eno dna ,epolakcaj live na htiw rehtona
a sa ot derrefer si tnuH dliW eht ,syadawoN
dna ti dniheb nwod gnireknuh dnab eganeet dias erutcip tsuj dluoc I dna ,selbat
,retaw fo elttob a erew stekcaj ruo htaeneB .drocer ot ahtnamaS rof kcab deef eht gniyaler
.arepo paos a naht relats gnimoceb saw siht sa ,daeh ym koohs I
.nirg a htiw em gnieye ,sthgil daehrevo eht morf gnitnilg gnir gniddew reh
”?ay era ,ereh lacol
,wap deteerg a htiw gnimialcorp ,retnuoc eht dniheb morf pu depmuj ylneddus erugif a nehw
knahT“	         ”.dnuora eseht fo ynam oot dnif t’nac lleh sa eruS“
.yrots olos nwo sti eb dluoc flesti dnekeeW tsoL eht ,ytsenoh lla nI
skool niatrecnu dedart eiruaL dna ,ahtnamaS ,naeD .gnihtemos
.sruo fo tnorf ni gnidnats naeD dna em gnivael
”,ton ro detlusni eb dluohs I fi wonk t’nod
,krans napdaed a ni detpurretni naeD
”,tuoba gniklat er’ew ahtnamaS si
,royam tsrif sti sa ,taht ekoj edisni na morf detanigiro eman s’nwot eht deveileb s’tI“ .denialpxe eh
.seidooh ruo nwod gnileep eiruaL dna em ta rewolg ot
enoyreve ,gninrom yadnoM stes noisivelet dna soidar rieht
”!aznagavartxE neewollaH launnA s’yteicoS sretnuH lamronaraP eht ot ,sretceps dna skoops ,emocleW“ .reyof ecnartne
rotceted dleif FME na dna
”!yllaniF“	         .yrotsih gnitsur ,gnippihc sti pu evig ot desufer tub
eht htiw trilf ot ton yrt
ot detcepxe tsomla em fo traP
.reh rof nepo rood eht dleh I erehw
,srekcits lacitilop
eht lla spahrep tub ,syad yrolg sti morf ,yldettimda ,dedaF .eybdooG fo nwot eht
,ygolana noteleks eht eunitnoc ot dedeen I fI
.erots scinortcele s’elcnu reh ta boj yad tnellecxe na gnitteg dna egelloc ot gniog retfa nevE
,ymmaS ,yeH“ .srae ruo ni sdnuos odanrot eht revo gnihgual ,em deksa eiruaL
.S.H.P eritne eht dna em ,thginot os dna
.emit ni nezorf-flah gnidliub eht ot tol gnikrap dekcarc eht ssorca dekkert I sa doG fo tca na ekil gnimool
,ereh tuo thgir gnidnats era werc
,moob yna ekil dna
,revewoH .resserd nedoow eht no noisivelet golana na gniees ton ta dehgis-flah I dna
,elihwnaeM	         .semitemos rekammlif suoires a emoceb t’ndid ehs yhw rednow netfo em edam woh-wonk noitcudorp-tsop dna slliks gnitide hguoroht reh ,tcaf nI
.secnaraeppasid elbaton fo elpuoc a sa llew sa
,gninaelc neeb d’eh taht tohs ssalg eht no deppat sregnif dewalc sih fo eno nehW .raeb lacizziuq eht deksa I
.smoor ruo ot rodirroc tnecajda eht nwod klaw ot detrats ew sa ni demihc eiruaL
.ecafrus eht ot delbbub pihsnamselas nwo ym
,detuohs naeD ”!ojenoc ,renwo
”.peelsa gnillaf retfa syad eerht pu ekow
deppalc I	         .denord naeD ”.ojenoc
,gnidda ,egaggul ym gnippirg retfa dias I ”,hguone
,lleH eht tahw tub
tsriF“	         ”.si sa eciffo eht ta uoy htiw emit gnidneps yojne yldrah I“
taorht ym fo kcab eht depacse hgis a
.spil ym dekac taht tsud dna dnas dniheb dennirg I ”,thgir ydal a taert ot doog s’tI“
yrots s’thginoT dna
larutanrepus eht rof rotceted latem a ekil fo dnik
,ylpeed delahni eH
”,sknahT“	         ”.oot uoy rof yek
.lag senecs-eht-dniheb dna namowaremac a sa hguoht rovaf reh ni dekrow fo tros tI
ekil tsuj ,hguoht srotagitsevni lamronarap era ew tub ,’scihcysp tnec-owt‘ emos tsuj t’nera I dna werc ym ,drocer eht roF“
esoporp ot dah enoemos ,aedi eht detah I sa hcum sA
emihc detadtuo nA
.aremac-ffo seye sih gnillor naeD dna selggig delffum s’eiruaL gnirongi elihw
.ruoF“	         *** .yliranidroartxe dekrow
redluohs sih dettap eiruaL
,serutluc naisenyloP eht dna aisA tsaehtuoS ot eporuE nretsaE morf
,ezah s’dniw eht hguorht ;66 etuoR yb detcesib dna lateleks dna erabdaerht
,renroc siht ni dnA .yad s’tnias lla gnidecerp yletaidemmi thgin eht ,nwoT tsohG eht ,tnuH dliW eht :snrettap railimaf eht fo egdelwonk htiw demrA .rotagitsevni lamronarap ,ffilchtaeH marB ,renroc siht nI  ”.letoH kcirevaM“
yadnoM txen eht pu ekow dna
srotagitsevni lamronarap er’eW“ .pu ekops eiruaL ”,era yehT“
ydal a tub ,sey ,namoW“
sihT“	         ”…orPoG a tegrof t’ndid ew ,yllufepoH
,edisdaor yletelpmoc toN
.pu tel ton dah mrots eht taht reh htiw dehgis ylevitcelloc I dna
yrotsih fo rorrim weivraer eht ni raf os tsap s’ytic gniltsub a fo srednimer
”.cissalc lanigiro eht ,wonk uoY“ .gninnirg deilper I
,setad/seman fo sgnivrac dehcte
,tsap sedaced morf mug desu ,deird fo sdaw dilos dna
,sknahT“	         ”,marB ,uoy knahT“ ,delims
letoM ratS treseD eht dellac ssenisub depahs-L ,yrots-elgnis eht
”.tnih eht teg I .haey ,haeY“
.traeh yb ti gniticer fi sa dias ehs
.elggig gnihsulb a kcab thguof ahtnamaS sa derekcins I dna eiruaL hcihw ot
,tniap fo taoc hserf a dedeen ti ,erutcetihcra eht ni sehcra devruc dna sroloc letsap eht fo tser eht ekiL