.meht ot enod eb dluoc taht gniht tsrow eht si tnemom taht ot kcab nekat gnieb ekil
tsuJ“ .detalitnevrepyh I
,eceiprae ym otni dellac I
enoemos fo daetsni ,ti dniheb wap larutanrepus fo tros emos dah skoob fo kcats degnarra yltcefrep yreve gnikniht eb d’I ,did I fI .larutanrepus
.ssensuoicsnocnu morf nesir dah naeD dna ahtnamaS ,oga setunim
,liat ekil-nottoc gnilggiw ym fo esab eht delkcit kraps cirtcele nA
.pu flesym tuhs dna tesolc ym otni nar
.stnerrot laudarg ni em ot kcab dedoolf thgin suoiverp eht fo stneve ehT
sa tuo now tsomla tsul ,daetsnI
.enap ssalg eht kcurts
,)sdrac ssenisub ruo
usu naht regnort—
,langis on ,srab oN
nettor eht ,ainrofilaC rof pu kcap ot dediced nosdivaD eteP
,hcneb eht ot detcennoc tsif yM .gnihtoN ”!?eiruaL“
,yldipar deknilb eH
rehgih gnidnecsa dna gnisir
saw sega rof reh htiw kcuts taht eramthgin enO
.em rof gniht railimafnu na t’nsaw sdnal regnarts dna ssenkrad etelpmoc-raen ni enola gnieB *** ”?gnidloh
dnoces eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
”?drazzilb tresed eht ni uoy dnif ot gniyrt ereht tuo dneirflrig
,noos dne ll’ti ,yllufepoH
,raeppasid ot detrats yks thgiliwt eht ssorca deparcs thgilnus revetahW
.em htiw trilf ot gninnigeb ylneddus sinodA lacol a fo rovaf ni ti derongi I tub ,dnim ym fo kcab eht ta erehwemos dewalc gnileef gniggan A .kcab dennirg I dna
.sisylarap peels ereves htiw pu werg I ?em rof sA
”!enoyreve ,neewollaH yppaH“
.dehgual eiruaL ,nehT
,weiv fo tuo dna ni derekcilf yehT
.slennut ruof eht fo yna nwod og t’ndid ehs
.tey em tih t’ndid mrots a gnirud 66 etuoR raen gnideeps eb dluow kcurt modnar a yhw fo thguoht ehT
.krow t’ndid noitacidem eht nehw enas em peek ot htob meht no deiler ot ,ytisrevinu otni gniog loohcs hgih morf ,oS
der fo htnirybal a gniretne flesreh dnif dluow ehs ,edisni nwod bmilc
.emit doog a rof gnikool tsuj ,ereh tuo
.revo retto eht dekool yliraw I
sa tsuj…mih no rettaps doolb eht sa der sa tsuj
.edisa ti devaw eH
”…reh dnif og nac I dna
.tuo ti gnillup ,tekcop ym ni enohp ym rof delfir I .derettum I ”,em kcuf
”?gnihton teg ew did kcuf
.em dniheb gniklaw s’enoemos ekil yllufwa ,gnihtemos raeh ot trats I ,nwod yawflah nehw ,66 etuoR nwod gniklaw m’I dna ,ytpme
.mrots eht ni detarapes tog eiruaL
,resolc deppets retto ehT
.tuhs nug-a-fo-nos taht kcol dna reliart ym ot teg I
.htuom dna eson ym otni gnitteg morf dnas eht gnikcolb deirt I sa tnemevap tneicna gnola delbmuts teef ym
em ot klat eciov s’naeD draeh I
,draob klahc a no slian ekil detcapmi srae ym ni gnignir ehT
!marB“ *** .tuo dessap I…
.gnithgil larutannu dna kcirb
”.kcarc ssa s’nwad was I litnu tuo keep erad t’ndid I
”.sgniht gniees s’ti ,thgin ta sgniht gniraeh
.sgnul ym fo pot eht ta deerga I ”!sey
”?eiruaL ,taht raeh uoy diD“ ”!won kcab teg—
.evitcepsrep s’deef ym gniwohs ,deb eht no denodnaba yal retupmoc potpal ehT
,ffilchtaeH marB   ”.letoH kcirevaM“
.thgirla saw eiruaL fi wonk ot snaem a ron langis a
.etal oot tsomla thgiltops a ekil ssenkrad ydnas eht hguorht debbats sthgildaeh ehT
hcihw ,seirots tsohg eht rof emac eW
!KNOH !KNOH !KNOH —yrautcnas ym rof tnew dna dnuorg eht tsniaga dekcik I ,thguoht hcum tuohtiW
tsael ta ,dab taht yllaer t’nsi mrots ehT
.rufdaeh sih gnikahs dna sworb sih morf dnas emos gnipiw elihw delkcuhc eh ”,ysae ,ereht ysaE“
,tsirw ym psarg
,dnuorg eht kcurts thgilhsalf yM
.nav .S.H.P eht evird ot dereetnulov naeD
.flesreh gnirehtag retfa deretlaf elims s’eiruaL
”.nwot siht si os dna ,desruc era uoY“
.eiruaL rof ytinrete ekil tlef tahw rof deunitnoc ti ,semit rehto tub
.niaga os od yldalg
.egatoof derehtag eht lla deyevrus ahtnamaS
,draobdaeh eht tsniaga detser srae yM
.enif s’ehs erus ytterp m’I“
.lla ta smaerd yna evah ton
.eceiprae ym ni ylbisneherpmocni
,66 etuoR otno su dereets leehw eht ta flow nacixeM eht sa daeha thgiarts derats I .yawa dekool I
.thgilhsalf eht no pirg ym htiw deniarts eciov yrd yM ”?uoy era ohW“
dluow dna semit derdnuh a meht dlot d’yeht fi sa
…yllanif litnu rehgih dna
.sesion gnippat tniaf decudorp yehT
,tnemevap nevenu s’66 etuoR revo gnippets no desucof oot neeb d’I
.selkcuhc gniveilebsid sih sserppus ot deliaf dna deirt naeD ”.marB ,uoy ylnO“
,ysaeuq gnileef taorht dna suoesuan hcamotS
”,dias tsuj eh tahW“
eh sa htaed dna efil neewteb gnirekcilf
sih dna ,trihs dialp a htaeneb selcsum fo riap gnorts a edih ot elttil did tekcaj siH
gnivilnu eht woh tub
,egelloc fo syad detimil ym dna loohcs hgih ni kcaB
.yawhgiH 04-I eht ot su gnitcennoc
,rehtruf denialpxe miJ sa giws elgnis a ni elttob eht nwod delzzug flow ehT
llew sa ,peels MER retfa dna ,gnirud
)a ew taht noitidnoc eht no(
emoceb seciov eht deciton I erom eht
”!revetahw…fffP“ .detcerroc miJ
”,mmH“ .resolc em gnillup ,liat ym fo esab eht
.tey nwod esolc t’ndid elpaM no erots erawdrah rehto eht nehw ,kcab sraey os ro nevele saw was I gniht ehT
”?ypoc uoy od ,ahtnamaS“
.deregnil tresed ylno litnu gnihtyreve gniflugne
.sraey neeterp ym ecnis ecneirepxe raluger a neeb d’ti eugra dluoc eno ,tcaf nI
.elttob sih fo tser eht knard neht ,gnihtemos delbmurg eH ”.dratsab
,semitemos ;neppah dluow sgniht fo yteirav a ,tnew lrig amup gnuoy eht reverehW
.deggeb ew hcum woh rettam on ,esaec ot desufer esion eht dna
efas m’I kniht I
,buc amup elttil a sa maerd emas tcaxe eht evah ot desu ehs ,sraey eht revo em dlot eiruaL tahw morF
.niaga deneppah ti ,ylnedduS
”.tihs kcaj lla s’ti
em eracs t’ndid yeht ,gnitnahc dehsuh ot nika sdniw
dluoc ehs erofeB
.sruoh evlewt rof peelsa neeb
.drazzilb treseD“ ,delkcuhc eH
”!deneppah ti taht ecnedive fo derhs on tog ev’ew won dnA
otni wolley egnaro-ekup morf gnihtyreve denrut mrots tsud ehT
.ecnartne eht otni renroc sti dnuora detfird neht
.suoiresnu sa ssimsid dluow ynam taht elor a
,snoitseuq ffo gnitsil nageb I
:sedosipe eht ot snoitulos yraropmet owt derevocsid I ,trohs yrots gnol a ekam oT
detarbiv sllaw ehT ”!pots ti ekaM !pots ti ekam ,doG ’nikcuf yB“ .roolf
,smelborp pihsnoitaler
.edistuo desaec yldrah seciov eht tub ,tuhs dehsarc tI .reh htiw edisni degnulp I dna ,nepo rood tnorf eht deknay eiruaL
“ ,yas naeD draeh ylno I
eciohc a ekam t’ndid ehs
,deraeppa ti sa tsaf sa tsuJ
”…edisni teg ,edisni teg
.tip eht otni nwod gnippets dna spets sseldne eht nwod gniklaw reh htiw nageb tI
denoitisop saw ti tsael ta
.derednaw dnim ym ,srohcna ekil thgilhsalf dna enohp ym dehctulc I sa gnittis
.tnemom yrev taht litnu detaicerppa reven I eno emas ehT
aedi on htiw ,ocixeM weN fo egde eht no nwot nwodnur a fo elddim eht ni retlehs sub a ni kcuts saw I ,won dnA
sa rednetrab eht ot gnivaw
,deilper ylduol I ,dniw dira ,gnilwoh revO
.ssenkrad deduorhs eht hguorht enohs ngis s’letom eht dna yawhcra ehT
,rab a ni stnediser eybdooG emos weivretni
.reduol steg tsuj ti ,kcen ym nwod gnihtaerb s’reveohW
reduol dehceercs yeht ,gnihtyna fI
,dedivorp ylippah tneK dna miJ
.tih neeb ev’dluow I dna toof rehtona tsuJ
,srae rieht derevoc flow nacixeM dna lerriuqs htoB
.tey srac motnahp oN .teerts eht gnissorc erofeb syaw htob deye I ,emit sihT
.deksa I ”?sgniht fo sdnik tahW“
.nees eb ot sniamer ,deveilebsid ro
raew tsuj t’ndid eH
.rebos yats ot sgniteem AA ot og em dah dna spukooh lauxes desu regnol on I
.eidooh reh deppord ehs etunim eht eiruaL did sa
yllanif litnu nur I os
,61 mooR no stsif ruo mals dna rodirroc eht nwod elbmut saw od dluoc eiruaL ro em llA .sthguoht ym tuo gninword dna smurdrae ruo ni gnignir ,reduol dna
tibbarkcaj lauxesnap
hcum a nrut seye krad sih dessentiw I ,dnoces tilps a roF
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.daeherof ym otno selggog eht deleep bmuht yM
.sgniht eciton ot trats ay ’na efil ruoy lla nwot -desruc siht ni eviL“
gnitarbelec & cisum evawropav ot gninetsil emit eerf sih sdneps ohw
larutanrepus eht htiw sretnuocne rieht tuoba su dlot
”?retlehs sub a ni teem ay regnarts tsrif eht htiw trilf syawla uoy od…uoy oD“
,tiaW“ ”!era ew ereh dna ,deeps pot ta pots sub a fo tuo gnideeps ay ees I nehT .seciov eseht gniraeh detrats I nehw ay dnif ot gniyrt ,dnuora gnirednaw neeb d’I tub ,rehtie tnew uoy erehw onnud I“ .reh dewollof I dna ,pirg eciv a ni tsirw ym dleh eiruaL ”!yaw sihT“
.reirrab eht tsniaga gniparcs ro ot gnikcits dnas fo niarg hcae gniliated
.tiaw saw od dluoc I lla
daetsni ot esohc ehs fI
,enap ssalg eht tsniaga ylduol deppat gnihtemoS
eb ot deneppah gnihtemos fi tuo gnirugif nehw thguoht lanoitar yawa worht t’ndid I ,citpekS .rM gnieb rof naeD desaet I sa hcum sA
”!eiruaL ,ti ees I“ .feiler rettu ni delkcac I ”!ti ees I“ ”!marB ,’niog peeK
:yawhgih ytpme eht ot tnecajda daor eht nwod deraeppa ti ,did I nehW
gnirebmemer eb ot tnaw t’nod yllaer yeht gnihtemos gnirebmemer si enoemos nehw
,flow neknurd eht demrofni I ,tneK ot nevig elims citehtapmys a dna rae dedlof a htiW
.eidooh eht rednu ,daeh ym pota gnittis aremac eht derebmemer I ,neht tlef I revetahw gnirongI
,erutcurts eht ot detnirps I
.sniuqennam ekil em ta gnirats dna gnidnats
”?evlewT“ ”…saw thgin tsaL
lla s’teerts eht ,si ti ereh oS
a tog uoY ?uoy tuoba tahW“
”.neK ,thginot uoy rof hguone s’taht kniht I“
.sweivretni ruo dedrocer dna denetsil gnivah
eiruaL fI .levon erutnevda-nwo-ruoy-esoohc a fo sgnidne eht ekil ,yltnereffid egnahc dluow eramthgin eht ,ereht morF
.sevlesmeht ti dessentiw ohw esoht ot lohocla nevig d’eh tub ,dnekeeW tsoL suomafni eht retfa gnol egnuoL odaroD lE eht gnitarepo neeb dah raeb ylzzirg eht ,notsnraB miJ roF
”,mrots tsud eht gnirud tsol tog I nehw ,thgin tsaL“
litnu emit fo tnuoma etanoitroporpsid a rof spets eht nwod klaw
?thgilhsalf ruoy ot deneppah tahW-
”,moor txen eht ni sgniht reh pu gnikcap ydaerlA“
.pleh em tog stnerap ym ,retrohs neve yrots regnol a ekam oT
mlap ym morf detcelfer wolg der raelcnu nA
delttes duolc tsud eht litnU
ev’ew ,ssensuoires lla nI“
.thgilhsalf ym fo wolg wolley eht ekil
dna larips ot eunitnoc egassem etuorne na gnitacidni noci ralucric eht dehctaw seye gniretaw ym ,setunim lareves roF
,mrots tsud ereves a gnirud nwot nacixeM weN gniyd a fo elddim eht ni saw I .hguoht
.kcab kool ot ton derad I tub ,swodahs eht fo erom dettops I erows I ,selggog ytsim eht hguorht dna eye yraet a fo renroc eht nI
.laer saw ti fo enon flesym dnimer ot dedeen I erehw elttab lacigolohcysp a otni denrut
,hcrop ym no doots ti tub ,ti llac nac I yaw
.tekcaj fo dnik emos ni retto na saw eh derevocsid I ,mih ta thgil eht gninihS
.anemonehp larutanrepus fo retnec nwodnur ,suoiretsym eht deyats eybdooG
,kool taht teg syawla yeht—
.teef ym ot kcab em gnillup
dna taebtraeh ym ekil hgih gnisir tub hctip ni degnar erew yehT .retlehs eht fo edistuo ,oot seciov
.taews eb ot kcils ro ykcits oot yaw dna
,lauxesrepyh a gnieb htiw denibmoc msilohoclA
,mraw gnihtemos tlef I .ezeerf
,ecno roF .reh fo tnorf ni ro dniheb ,thgir reh ,tfel reh ot eno eht toN
.wap s’rentrap amup ym dnuora sregnif devolg ym gnizeeuqs ,derelloh I
.llet t’ndluoc I ,nav a ro kcurt a rehtiE
ot seciov erom yna rof ylno ,sessalg rieht desiar ro dereehc snortap wef a ,su dniheB
yteicos yreve tuB
.noisiced a edam dna nav gnivom-wols eht fo tnorf ni ecnad tsud fo slriws dehctaw I ,ylpeed gnihgis dna
.nworb yenoh krad
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.detfihs yeht ,semit rehto tub ,egarim a sa laer sa demees yeht ,semitemoS
.ecirht dna ,eciwt
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb
”.slrig otni ton m’I“
esimorp em edam dna neethgie denrut ehs tnatsni
.esacriats eht morf gnippets retfa
ot em desuac hcihw fo htob ,xes dna lohocla
.si ehs erehw onnud I .detarapes erew I dna eiruaL dna ,66 ffo erehwemos noitats sub a ni tsol m’I tub ,aremac ym hguorht gnikool llits er’uoy fi erus ton m’I ,ahtnamaS ,naeD“
.peelsa saw I nehw pu edam dnim eht tahw ot derapmoc tihsllub erew noitanigami gnikaw ym fo stnemgif suoivbO .smaerd ym ni nees d’I tahw ot derapmoc
.dad dna mom ym llac ot sa raf os tnew I ,speeb erew dne rehto eht no enohp ym morf gnimoc sdnuos ylno eht nehW .s’ahtnamaS dna
wap dilos a tlef I litnu
.em ot derrucco ti
lla tI .emoh ylimaf reh ni pu gniworg
.daeh ym fo kcab eht ni em deknoc skcirb
.nwodkaerb latnem a gnivah sa llew sa ,devol I nam eht htiw pihsnoitaler a gnidne em ot del taht htap evitcurtsed-fles a no tnew I ,sretsemes wef a nihtiW
”.sllac ym rewsna t’now dna
deraef eb ot era srewsna esoht rehtehw
,hguone knurd tsael yrev eht ta ro ,hguone suoegaruoc esoht fo amuart desserper dna noisufnoc reehs eht debircsed eH
,ybbol letom eht ni hcolB .srM dnif ot deliaf dna deirt naeD elihW
”.kcab thgir eB“ .rood moordeb eht rof tnew eiruaL
”,naem ay ,seiromeM“
.tnempiuqe lacirtcele eht fo emos em gnidnah ,oot moor letom rehto eht fo tuo emac ahtnamaS
.sdoirep eseht gnirud yregami gniyfirret etanicullah sa
.llits doots ehs etunim eht tug reh tih
,em dniheb pu hcaer wap
.ylevisnefed pu swap htob dleh eH
tseb ym deirt I ,os ro ruoh txen eht roF
,oot thgin tsal morf seciov eht draeh
.tisiv ot tnew I emityna sklof reh htiw pu cipot eht gnirb reven ot
”.ni neeb ev’I seno eht ot derapmoc
ym dekac dnas hcum revewoh dna secrof elag eht gnitsiser
.oot did I dna retnuoc eht ssorca miJ htiw swap koohs eiruaL ”,su htiw kaeps ot emit eht gnikat rof hcum os uoy knahT“
,dekool ti sa elbatrofmoc sa tlef ti fi erac neve t’ndid I .kaerc elbidua na htiw
.hgih pu srae ym dekrep I
”?ahtnamaS s’erehw ,thgin tsal deneppah kcuf eht tahW“
?eiruaL ?naeD ,gab moorhtab ruoy ni niripsa yna toG“ .mlap ym htiw ti debbur I sa gninaorg ,daeh ym dekcoc I
.elbanigami edis yreve morf muinarc ym ecreip seldeen toh gnileef ,roolf eht no gnileenk ot derapmoc revognah oN
mraw a tlef I neht saw tI ”.taht ekil I
,retaw eb ot kciht oot diuqiL .tew dna
.niaga ti raeh ot tnaw t’nod I dna ,efil ym ni draeh reve d’I hceeps yna
”.em ot neewollaH yppaH…retarg eseehc a htiw em kcuf ,lleW“ .gnihtoN
,won rof tub ,ti revocer ot gniyrt s’ahtnamaS dna wohemos dekcuf tog oidua ehT .marB
.ydob s’mitciv hsarc a ot
dlot neht eH .der ’nikcuf
,em ta ton ,ylirgna delrans eH
ot derewol sregnif siH
.tekcaj rehtael deidoolb a ni desserd
.rekihhctih flowerew
,teef ym ot pu dekrej I dna tuo deglub seye yM ”.syad owt
,keew lufsserts a ot eud maets lauxes ffo wolb ot gnitnaw
,rekrad nworg dah gnihtyrevE
.dnas eb ot ti rof drah oot saw ti ,ylnO
ehs mrifnoc dluoc ew os dnuora nrut ot naeD gniksa dna ecneserp reh tuo gnitniop ,pu gnikaeps naht rehtaR
...dias tahT .taht
.yltcaf-fo-rettam detaeper eh ”,gnihtoN“
s’naeD yb dewollof
.pu denethgiarts I ”?huH“
.htarw dira s’erutan rehtoM morf em dleihs ot
.pu dnuorg eht morf .S.H.P dliub em depleh ehs erofeb neve ,tsegnol eht rehto hcae wenk eW
,keew a ecno deneppah
”?ees uoy did tahW“ ”.ti ees
.daor eht gnola yaw ym dnif ot gniyrt
,seires yrots naipotsyd yrruf gniogno sih sa hcus seirots rehto dnif osla nac uoy erehw ,noertaP sih no ,htnoM tumS retsnoM gniogno na htiw neewollaH
.ztilgitS .rM ,taht hguorht tnew uoy yrros m’I dnA“
tpecxE .tip eht otni depmuj eiruaL dna ,tuo
.ydaets dnats ot tseb ruo gniod
,kcuF“ ”!egdod ot kcab lleh eht teg s’tel ,nom’C“
.rehto hcae htiw gnihtyreve dedifnoc ew
,eb ot deneppah rotagitsevni dael-oc ym erehw
,em kcuf ,em kcuF“
llits dnats ot esohc
eb ti rehtehw ,rehto hcae depleh eW
,ruf keehc ym otni roloc emos kcab hsaw dna moorhtab eht ni flesym eveiler ot tnew I sA
.od ot tahw tuo erugif dna mlac niamer ot
”.si ti sa hguone naht erom tog ev’ew kniht I“
.kramkcehc neerg eht otni nrut ot reven ,larips
,sicoV sumoD yb
.ohce na ekil tsol eb
decniw I ”!wo ,wo ,wO“
derevocsid ew naht
rof…tuo lla su dekconk ti ,thgin tsal deneppah revetahW“
dna…wodniw eht tuo kool I litnu
detseggus niarb ym fo trap suorehcel erom ehT
dna stnahc gnimmuh otni demrofsnart yehT .reduol
,rebmun s’eiruaL llac ot deirt neht ,delrans I
.mrots tsud eht otni tuo kcab nar gnikcuf I dna
,gnihton ’nikcuf tog eW“
!retlehs pots sub dlo na
ekil dnuos t’ndid ti…doG-G .’uoy era os dna desruc si nwot sihT‘ ,em ot dias…em
”—uoy did woH ?tnediser a uoy erA
.detcepxe naht suonieh erom dna rekrad secalp ot tnew ti tub ,taht ylno toN
.tnemtrapa reh ni tpels eiruaL thgin tsrif eht no dedne seramthgin eht ,wonk I sa raf sA
.egufer fo ngis yna rof selggog eht hguorht gnireep deirt I ,emit eritne ehT
...tI .t’nsaw ti…ti tub ,ega ym lammam a ekil dekool tI“
,rentrap ym dna em tub ,thginot nwod gniog ffuts ykoops eht fo emos golatac
tsuj I .ffirehs eht llac ot kniht neve t’ndluoc I ,sdnilb eht gnittuhs retfa draeh I sdnuos gniliaw eht dnA .gnippos dna ,laruttug ,yvaeh tsuJ
”?ypoc uoy od ,naeD ro ymmaS ,taeper I
.em fo tnorf ni nwod ekorb eiruaL ,txen deneppah tahw otni teg
degnoleb taht sraet prahs dnuof I
thgin eht rof nwod erots eht dnuow
.dluoc I sa yllausac sa deggurhs I ”,od I sseug I ,haeY“
,dne daed a dnif did ehs nehw dedne eramthgin eht ,semitemoS
”!letom eht ot kcab gniog teg retteb eW
.srodirroc gnitcennocretni ro sdne daed yna evah reven ot demees hcihw
.tahc ffats s’yteicoS sretnuH lamronaraP eht ot egassem txet a gnidnes daetsni ,erac t’ndid I tub ,em dednilb neercs thgirb ehT
”.nomed a htiw detrilf I kniht I“ ,pu ekops I
reh fo maeb eht neve toN .dnuof eb ot erehwon saw rotagitsevni-
.kcab welf tsomla ti nehw eidooh ym fo tnorf eht deppirg I ”!?oot meht raeh uoy
.rehtaew eht yb thguac wohemos ,ydnac
,seceiprae s’eiruaL dna em otni derettum ahtnamaS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.degnahc yldrah ecaf s’retto ehT
,hgU“ .seye ym morf tsurc deird eht gnibbur elihw
ees ylera—h kcab te—
peelsa ton saw I
gnileef ysaenu na debircsed eiruaL
,em ta dennirg eH
,lautca ro dnim dekips-enilanerda ym fo kcirt a ti eB .nar llits I tub ,em retfa emoc t’ndid
ytpme eht fo eno tsniaga dehcnuh I
saw I sa ,reh emalb t’ndluoc I
,tuhs rood eht mals eiruaL dna em did renoos oN .hguoht yrautcnas dedivorp gnihtoN .yek a gnissessop derebmemer I erofeb
pat duol rehtonA
”!llorcSelzzuM no knil a em dnes dnA
.reisae leef sgniht ekam t’ndid ytilaer ot gninruteR .noitazilivic
.wap ym gnizeeuqs reh morf emac noitamrifnoc fo ngis ylno eht ,ylper reh denword mrots tsud
,dnuora delrihw I sa nees eb dluoc thgilhsalf
.deirrow t’nsaw I naem t’ndid ti tub ,tsrow eht gnimussa rof flesym dedihc em fo trap A
ot ereh m’I .on ,lacol ton m’I“
”.hgu…yna gnirb t’ndid kcuf sa erus I
.rood eht morf deraeppa xof dega-elddim a nrows ev’dluoc I ,tol gnikrap eht fo tuo gnillup elihW
ksed eht ta ton s’ehS“ .detaeper eh
d’I dna ,ereht reganam eht eb ot desu I
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sthguoht ym morf em gnirrits
”?hcolB .srM tuoba tahW“
,eybdooG“   yojne esaelP
.wollip a otni daeh ym yrub ot gniyrt em dna ahtnamaS ediseb gnileenk eiruaL htiw ,sdeb
.evah yllautca dluohs rehto yna naht hteet detniop erom dleh htuom nepo siH
noisufnoc dna thgirf ni demaercs I
.reh ediseb tas eiruaL
”!tihs yloh ,tihs yloH“
,dlrow eritne eht derevoc hcihw mrotsdnas citpylacopa na fo rovivrus tsal eht sa flesym denoisivne I
fo not a ekil gnileef roolf eht morf pu depmuj I ,eciov s’naeD gniraeH ”!pu ekaw ,marB
”.ereht uoy deracs I yrroS“
.wap gnivaw a htiw delkcuhc eiruaL
a ro yot a sa hcus smaerd reh otni deelb dluow dlrow laer eht morf sgniht
.pots em edam ti ,did I nehW
depraw eciov cinortcele s’ahtnamaS nevE
,relevart wollef ruoy
”!gniog peek attog eW“ .dehgual I
.seirc gniliaw
,kcab detuohs ehS ”!od I“
seriuqer ti selor eht rof seman tnereffid sah
rehtien dah I ,mrots tsud eht yb desuac ecnerefretni revetahw ot sknahT
.ecalp siht dnuof I nehw ereh hguorht gnissap tsuj saw I“
.em fo tnorf ni deps ylneddus elcihev A
.txetnoc dda ot ni demihc semitemos sreograb gniniamer eht elihw
enola lla ,tibbar ynnub emosdnah a :uoy dnif I ereh
remrof eht evig ew
.cinot dna nig a nortap rehtona dednah eh sa seye sih dellor miJ
ahW“ .gnihtemos yas reh draeh I ,dnoces tilps a roF
,pots sub eht fo ssalg eht morf detcelfer thgil eht ,taes hcneb eht no em ot txen thgilhsalf eht gnitteS
eht ro ,gnihtyna yas t’ndid eiruaL rehtehW
,su neewteb thgilhsalf eht debbarg ylwols I nehw toN
.detpurretni eh ”,gnihtoN“
dna enola lla ,retlehs sub eht ni ereht tas I sA
.rehtona dedivorp ylippah miJ
.em sdrawot gniklaw ,dniw eht tsniaga ylsseltroffe delbmuts yehT
.pu ekaw ay retfa stnemom sgniht semitemos...rorrim
,deunitnoc tneK ”,yawynA“
sa em detroppus yehT
,rood tnemesab reh fo tnorf ni pu ekaw d’ehs
thgin hcaE .ecaps lanosrep ym gnidavni
,etal oot sdnoces ytriht ro ytnewT
.naeD htiw eerga I ,ecno roF“
fo ngis tsal eht gnieb dnuof I xob latem-dna-ssalg eht htiw ,rovivrus a eb ot deneppah I ,kcul fo ekorts revetahw yB
.morf emac ti noitcerid eht ni thgilhsalf ym deppirg I ”?ereht s’ohW“
hcneb roiretni eht otno despalloc I ,htaerb ym gnirehtag fo sdnoces nihtiW
.roolf eht no deldduh ahtnamaS dna naeD
tsug gnorts ylralucitrap eno tub ,enacirruh a ekil yawa su fo rehtie yrrac ot hguone gnorts t’nsaw dniw eht ,yllufknahT
,yrros m’I“ .rood eht ta kool ot denrut I ,nehT
”.syug uoy ,niaga nwot siht ot kcab gnimoc os era eW“
,woN“ .emarf latem s’hcneb eht tsniaga deppat liat s’retto eht
,haN“ ”?sruoy fo dneirflrig a ehs si
.srewsna htiw nruter
.niaga tey rehto hcae ta dekool ew ,dnoces tilps a roF
,erofeb lortnoc elcsum esol ot em desuac snoitome doohdlihc desserper dna ecnalabmi lacimehc A
fo trap lanif dna
.nwot gniyd eht fo tser eht ruocs ot tuo sthgilhsalf ruo dellup ew dna
”.kcab su tnaw letom eht ta sdneirf ruo tub ,trohs lla siht tuc ot yrros m’I“
,gnihtaerb raeh I neht tub
ton s’taht ,sehctiB“
”,reh dnif t’nac eW“
.rorrim eht ni seye tohsdoolb ym ta deralg I sa knis nialecrop eht deppirg I ”?huH“
”!kcuf…srab orez evah ot semit eht lla fO“
”ocixeM weN ,eybdooG“
.egaggul ruo debbarg ew ,rehtegoT
.enim detcefni elims deveiler s'eiruaL
”!uoy s’ti ,marB—yloH“ .enog gnol saw doolb eht ezilaer em dah wap ym ta nwod ecnalg A
”!pots ti ekaM“
.lerriuqs denrecnoc eht ot deilper ylgnikoj I ”!tuo dna revO .dnammoC ,taht regoR“
...rorrim eht ni ,moor ruoy ni sgnihT
.ratrom dna kcirb dlo fo edam eloh egral a ot reh del ti
eht esuoh taht fo
.seciov cinortcele ,delbrag eroM
,serugif elbisivnon ,swodahs kraD
.swaj erauqs htiw nem rof gniht a evah ot deneppah I ,yeH
.ecnetsixe fo enalp rehtona
.sdlareme s’retto eht htiw dekcol seye ym sa
,kcab eht gnola lla dna
,wohemos detpurroc erew seliF“
ot mrots tsud a devarb eiruaL rotagitsevni-oc sih dna marB ,emit tsaL
”!?og ay did erehW“
.gnihgual detrats naeD dna ehs nehw dedihc I ”!ynnuf
.deltrats ,dias eh ”!yeh ,haoW“
erofeb kcab ,erots taht rof sgniht fo tol a od ot ot desu I—
,niaga gnikrow trats ot dediced
”!eiruaL ,ereht ay tsol tsomlA“
”.sweivretni eht sediseb
ztilgitS tneK dna notsnraB miJ ,retal setunim ytrof dna llib rallod-ytnewt A  2 fo 2 traP ,sicoV sumoD yb ”ocixeM weN
tseb eht s’taht ,llew...tI
.dekcarc eciov ym ”,tihS“
.gnitnuaH ehT ,smlif rorroh etirovaf ym fo eno morf enil a deticer ylikahs I ,epoc ot rehtar ro ,tcnitsni yB
,htnirybal eht nihtiw sretsnom ssorca gnimoc reh fo daetsnI
ton s’ti fI .ereh dnuor‘ neppah od sgniht egnarts ,neewollaH yrevE“
”?yllaer ,ereh tuo eb nac ew gnol woh swonk ohW
.tuons ym koohs I ”.yllaer ton
.pan elgnis a ni efil nwo ruoy fo syad elohw owt esol ot tlef ti woh mih llet ot
:rotagitsevni lamronaraP
.elbuort yna tuohtiw pu ekaw dluow ehs ,tip eht fo htuom eht tsniaga
nwod dekool neht
.mra ym no riah hcae
.noitseuq suoiverp ym derewsna eh ”,t’nod I ,oN“
,niaga seidooh ruo pu gnippiz dehsinif noinapmoc amup ym dna eM
.letom eht ot kcab teg ot yaw yna ro
.ti morf gnimoc seciov raeh dluow ehS
,srewsna yna htiw ocixeM weN eybdooG fo nwot eht morf nruter lliw eh rehtehw tub
eht ot aremac eht dessot dna tekcaj ym dehs I ecno nwod meht gnidlof dna srae ym gnibbarg ,dekrab I
.ti hctans ot kcab dehcaer I ,hguoht ylkciuQ .psarg
.dnim ym ssorc t’ndid seiceps ym fo mih gnitcerroc fo thguoht ehT
gniraeppaer dna gniraeppasid
pu em ekow eiruaL erofeb gnol ton ,woh denialpxe eH .rood nedoow eht hguorht
.spil s’eiruaL no nirg gnirevauq eht dettops I nehw naorg ot ylno
.gnihtyna eb ot laer oot tlef ti ,tnuh dliw taht…thgin tsal tub ,netfo oot tihs larutanrepus ni eveileb ot ton yrt I“ .kcul ruo tub
dna stirips fo dlrow eht otni yenruoj ohw snamahs eht htiw mih ssalc thgim yeht eppets nairebiS eht nO .yorT fo lybiS eht ekil mih eveilebsid dna ihpleD fo lybiS eht ekil mih raef thgim yeht eceerG tneicna nI .yalp ot elpoep
!raeh ay ,won erac ekat owt uoY“
ay fi ereh dnuora sretaert-ro-kcirt yna dnif t’ndluow uoy tub ,neewollaH s’tI .emoh rof teerts eht nwod gniklaw detrats d’I“
.ecnelis ylhtaed ni tas enoyrevE
.oidar eht no bonk noitats eht htiw dnuora deyot neht
.rab eht ni su fo hcae ot neht ,elttob sih ta nwod deralg tneK
,eciov gnippos ,ylevarg a ni derepsihw eH
tixe tsesolc eht otno ffo deeps dluow ew ,eybdooG ni sdoohrobhgien rehto fo dedeen ehs egatoof llor-B gniniamer eht tog ahtnamaS dnoces ehT
I saw dnah esohW“
,wodniw eht otni thgir gnikool
.kcab ym gnisserac
”.esrow steg mrots siht erofeb ratS treseD ot kcab teg d’I ,hguoht owt uoy erew I fI .tnemhsilbatse enif ym ni kcuf sa knurd teg ot noitidart ylraey a ti edam s’tneK yhw s’taht dnA“
oc dna dneirf ym dellac I ssenoil niatnuom lufituaeb ehT
.ecnartne tnorf eht tuo klaw ot detrats ew
.gnicar traeh dna gnitegdif teef
”?ojenoc ,gnileef uoy era woH“ ”?…ahw
.htaerb nekahs a ni derettu tneK ”,wonk t’nod I“
,drawretfa sliated eht rof deksa reven I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.thgil fo maeb eno ylno eciton ot waj rewol
.dniw gnimocni eht tsniaga gnihcnuh ,ylduol deksa I ”?eiruaL…hU“
,snrevac eht nwod detnirps ehs tsaf woh rettam on reh klats dluow erugif enol a ,semitemoS
lautcaf ,lautca tog ew em llet ,naeD“
raeh ot detrats osla I taht saw erom s’tahW
.yranidro eht fo tuo deraeppa gnihton ,esiwrehto tub ,thgis ni gnihtyreve derevoc dnas fo hcni na tsomla ,detnarG
.noitaudarg loohcs hgih erofeb htnom a tuoba ,xes gnivah detrats ew erofeb
.xaler ot detrats erutsop ffits yM .raeppasid seirrow ym edam wohemos elims
,rehtael saw tI .tekcaj raluger a
”ocixeM weN ,eybdooG“
.tuo teg saw od ot detnaw su fo yna lla ,tnemom eht roF
,seiratnemucod dlo ni yltsoM .semit wef a kool taht nees d’I dna
.srab eht ta ro peelsa rehtie era su fo tsom os ,deirt
!letom eht ees I ,tiaw ,tiaW“
.pots t’nseod ti ,em dniheb kool I semit ynam woh rettam on dna
enohptrams ym no ppa SPG eht ro
.teerts eht nwod ffo deps ti
.erofeb thgin eht ecnis degnahc yldrah eybdooG fo ees dluoc ew tahw dna tol gnikrap ratS treseD ehT
.nam eht ta kcab dna ,sregnif ym gnitaoc doolb eht ta
,66 etuoR ytpme eht ssorca drawhtuos su dediug I ,don mrif a htiW
.ecniw ot em dna woble ym pu tloj ot niap gnisuac
.msicitpeks dna ytilibisualp neewteb ecnalab a deriuqer snoitagitsevni lamronaraP ”?olleH“
htiw gnitrilf deirt tsuj I revetahW
.sngis gnidliub emos fo wolg noen larutannu eht tops ylerab dluoc I tniop eht ot
,nosmirc fo edahs rekrad
tsuj od dluoc ohw gnivil
tfos dna waj erauqs
”,kcehc og ll’I“
.elttob sih fo giws rehtona gnikat dehsinif neht ,denoitnem flow eht
.retlehs sub eht fo ecnartne eht ni gnidnats lammam rehtona dnif ot dnuora gninrut ,demaercs I ”?olleH“
elpoep wodahs cinomed dna setteuohlis dettah-pot deretnuocne I
.taes rac ym otni kcab dexaler I ,seye ym gnilloR ”.heh ,uoy ylnO“
.elzzum nat sih no dehcte nrecnoc eniuneg ,em deksa naeD
,ecnartne dekcolnu eht ot tog ew resolc eht tub ,tsud dna dniw eht tsniaga ngis ’ycnacav on‘ eht tuo ekam dluoc I
,noitanigami ym saw ti thguoht I ,tsrif tA
”!niaga sknaht ,llahs eW“
dna taes kcab eht ni redrocer oediv reh dleh ylteiuq ahtnamaS elihw taes regnessap tnorf eht ni pu delkcub I
”?yas tsuj uoy did tahW“
.tuo kcab taps yletaidemmi I trid enrobria eht yb tuhs yletaidemmi erew time ot deirt I smaercs ynA
erew yeht…seye sih ,dog hO
.krad eht ni sgnihT“
ot ylno…knalf sih dnuora ti parw ot mra ym dehcaer I
”,ekac eht sekat eno siht tuB
;eceiprae ym ni eciov on
.regnir lamronarap eht hguorht neeb htob d’ew esuaceb ylpmis ro
.dnim ot emac thguoht a litnu edaf ot nageb msimitpo yM
now ytisoiruc ,syawla sA
)b dna gnitide gnirud secaf rieht tuo rulb
”—odanrot tsohg a fo egatoof
.rovaf eht gninruter
.seciov eht ta knilb t’ndid eH
.thguob rehtaf reh noisivelet wen
tuo devom yletaidemmi ehs wonk did I tub
”,sesion elbaroda ekam ot woh wonk syawla yehT“
,em no skcirt derit yna gniyalp dnim ym eb ot ti rof duol ooT
,enap ssalg a otni gnimmals tsomla
.ria ytpme dnuora dehcnelc sregnif ym ,dnuora denrut I sA ”?tuo…eid ti diD
.oidar eht otni dellac I ”?eiruaL“
.wodniw reh morf toohs ot detnaw ahtnamaS sgnidliub fo wor a sdrawot
?dniw eht ni pu thguac tog taht dnas fo sniarg egral emos tsuj saw ti ebyam...dias
,dnas tresed fo sniarg dereyal eht neewteb swodahs fo sespmilg ees ylneddus dluoc I ,sretceps lautcaf
.hguoht dnekeeW tsoL eht rof mrots tsud a evarb tsuj t’ndid eW
ni flesym denigami I
.ylesnemmi reh deknaht htob eW .llew sa naeD ot emos dednah ehs dna ,rof reh deknaht ylippah I hcihw ,stelbat owt htiw denruter eiruaL .esactius ym dekcap dna moorhtab eht morf degreme I ,retal setuniM
””?ees ehs did tahW“
.selggig wef a sserper t’ndluoc flesreh ahtnamaS ”…uoy ylno ,haeY“
”!seiremmum…m esoht gnisare…heh ,ylwols m’I .eb t’noD“ ,deppuccih tneK ”.ztilgitS
.deregnil ti ,edulcnoc ot eramthgin eht rof gnitiaw egdel eht no doots ehs nehw ,erofeb semit rehto eht ekilnU
,ecno drah deknilb I
.elat sih ot gninetsil ,flesym detavitpac yrev
.lortnoc fo tuo larips ot em desuac
.nigriv a ekil derekcins yllufhsab I
,oS“ .hcneb eht no em ot txen nwod tas dna ecnartne eht morf yawa
.reh ssorca emac sretsnom nwo s’htnirybal eht
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.taes reh ni denael ehs sa ediw seye ,deksa eiruaL
fo eceip yarts a ot degnoleb tI
,peelsa llef ehs emit hcaE .keew loohcs a fo elddim eht ni syawla tsomla
.daeherof ym evoba ti derevoh I nehw
”?wonk ay ,tihs siht lla morf kaerb a ekat d’I thguohT
.s’tneK eb ot dah ti ,tuo doots taht seirots eht lla fo ,revewoH
?mrots siht hguorht teg uoy did woH“
s’eiruaL morf pils ot wap ym esuac did
.edis ym revo em dekconk yllautneve enO
.em ta nwod delims