,floWcaM boR si sihT
diovtraP yb meop a
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
.ereh krow rieht gnitubed si ohw ,diovtraP yb
,”enidanerG“   yojne esaelP
teef s’reidlos eht ta sllaf etanargemop eht
,relevart wollef ruoy
drahcro eht morf sesir ekoms  gnitsrub
,der gnippop ,gnissih ,gnizzif
nihc s’dlihc a nwod selbbird taht eciuj ezoo
slewej fo lluf si  etanargemop eht
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,diovtraP yb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
retaw dloc raelc gnilkraps otni deruop
yellav eht ssorca
.rekihhctih flowerew
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,gnieyd-regnif gniniats-draob-gnippohc
gniniatsus-yromem trat dna teews der
.yrteop rieht fo erom erahs ot ecnedifnoc eht evah noos ot epoh yehT
seohce pop eht sa
”enidanerG“ saw sihT
dna pop taht spip der-doolb ,tnaillirb