.drawyks dehcra noos smeg ekil sevael dna ,elbacalpmi
.teud lufegnahc emos ni ssarb ekil won gnirettahc
.ereht llits era ,dneirf ym ,uoY
.ecnelis ni denetsil I
.dewohs yalpsid lanif ruoy sa stra hcus gnissentiw ,kaeps neve ron
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitangats fo sraef ym fo klat d'I
uoy dna ,sdnal tnereffid fo syal tnereffid gnirolpxe
,denehtgnel moor eht
noitasrevnoc lufreehc ni rehtegot emit ruo tneps ew sa lufgninaem ssel on hguoht ,noos oot raf revo ro ,tneuqerf ssel ,retrohs
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.lior ot gnitrats hself
,noitatidem ruoy fo em llet d'uoY
ttocS nosidaM yb si meop s’yadoT
,smra dna stsirw ruoy pu delarips krab esraoC
,stseretni elkcif ym htiw pu tup d'uoY
,em ot yldnik os elims syawla d'uoY
,werg dna detuorps uoY
,uoy saw taht eert eht yb elihw a doots I
,”htworG“   yojne esaelP
.edam ydaerla eciohc a fo ekops hcihw
.ecneirepxe derahs ruo fo segnar eht lla hguorht em htiw gnola egnahc dna segnahc ym fo lla wollof d'uoY
.emit-tsaf ni gnittor
?yas I dluoc tahW
.sliart eht gnirettil secef rieht dnuora degdod ew sa neve
.tnereffid yllohw gnihtemos otni werg uoy woh ta ,uoy ta levram I
,tuo gnihcnarb em htiw
.snoitome dna sdrow gnillips
sevael detalenerc yb dewollof noos
,das ,sey ,saw elims ruoy dna ,dnop eht yb ereht
.gnidne yrev siht no ,demees ti ,deips uoy fo tser eht ,tnemom taht ni deid uoy fo trap sa
.ycnecedni fo emirc tsal eno gnittimmoc
.noitnetta ym stserra tahw ees ot gnippots ro ,em htiw gninnur
,hguoht ,thgir erew uoY  .rohpatem
,tuo yrc ton did I
,toir lanretni emos
?serac ohW ?sraeh ohW
,yad yreve sdleif eht klaw I
ton ro gniveileb rof emit on saw ereht ,saw ti sA
.straeh fo traeh ym ni osla deohce ,efil no esael siht pu evag uoy sa neve ,nees reven d'I sa ecaep hcus saw ecaf ruoy nI
?feirg-non siht seviecrep ohW
,seceip ot em deracs sdrib eht yhw ksa ton dna llits dnats em hctaw dluow
.sdrow ruoy naht rehtar esnes taht ot deilper I
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb meop a
--- ecneserp yrev ruoy yb ,demees ti ,denehtgnerts
.gib gnihtemos fo dne eht saw gnidner siht taht thguoht uoy em dlot uoY
,emoh deklaw I nehT
--- uoy no denrut ,dnuora devruc
!ecaf ruoy ,ecaf ruoY
.egnahc dna htaed ,noitamrofsnart
,sruoh rof klat dna esuoh eht fo kcab tuo sdleif eht hguorht klaw dluow yliad I dna uoy eb ot desU
ti hguoht dna gniklaw tuo tnew erom ecno ew ,yad eno neht dnA
?sevael gniltsur dna seert llits eht gnoma tuohs sseldrow ym raeh dluow ,tuo deirc I fi ,lla retfa ,ohW  .ytillun tog I
,ecnasaelp derehtag taht fo lla dima dna
,sdrow ni tup reven uoy thguoht fo senil gnirolpxe ,sdrawni gninrut
,yawa llef gnihtolc ruoY
.em dlot uoy taht ton tsael ta
.stnemom txen eht ni
.esnes ekam t'ndid dna depahs ylegnarts erew yad taht gniklaw ,em gnillet erew uoy sgniht ehT
.gnivael ruoy fo ruoh eht ecnuonna ot semihc on
,syaw etarapes ruo gniog eb ot demees hcae eW  .teiuq dnik ro
.kni.oykam ta revo
.klat dna esuoh eht fo kcab tuo sdleif eht hguorht klaw dluow yliad I dna uoy eb ot desU
,woh em dlot uoY  .flah ni uoy tib
.retaw teews fo gniknird reverof ,erohs eht yb uoy fo gnikniht ,teiuq ,enola
,tas uoy  woh fo em dlot uoY
,noisulla ,txetbus ,spahrep
.ecaps ruo erew ,sdnop htiw dettod ,sdleif ehT
,esneterp sa srenroc dnuora os did yeht ,did yeht fi rO
,seert eht ot tuo dekool
,traH ydrA yb uoy rof daer
,ti dessim ylraen yrev I dna semit etaciled hcus era sgninnigeB
,ssarg llat hguorht dna serohs gnola ecal ekil gnurts sliart esoht depmart eW
.pihsnoinapmoc ruo ni eerf os leef syawla d'I dna
,nwod enif ni derevoc
.etum dna dexif ,noitom htooms eno ni toor gnikat
,doow ydruts dna krab hguor ni derob elob a traeh ruoy ,sevael fo nworc a daeh ruoY
.eciov ruoy ni ti raeh dluoc I
,tsaf saw ecap ehT .smets enif dna
toohs rednet a detuorps nworc ruoy morf dna daeh ruoy dewob uoY
.htworg fo soahc eht ot smrahc dna snoitatnacni eltbus gnillepS
.gniklat ot tog uoy ,elihw a koot
.seev ni delleps mood ym dna snemo ees I ,sdrib ylno ees dna eseeg eht ot pu kool uoy elihW"
.elohw a sa demrofsnart ,demusnoc erew uoy ,nooS
.seye ruoy desolc dna
smeop dna seirots trohs morf ,gnitirw reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
,ereht ,ytilanif saw erehT
.stoor ytsriht sa
,htaerb wols a koot
doots seot dna ,seenk ,sregnif ruoy
.noitelpmoc fo ekops ecap yrev ruoy --- spets ruoy dna
,sdnah ruoy ,ecaf ruoy no tirw erew sgnidnE
..sedart lla fo flow a
,es rep ,bmun ton ,oN .bmun dna teiuq
.sisoehtopa eltneg ruoy ,egnar lanoitome ruoy ,efil ruoy
.sedart lla fo flow a
,rewols tog sklaw esoht ,emit revo dnA
,sdniw ekil won gnirumrum
,uoy tuoba thguoht I
,liomrut detcepxe I .teiuQ
.reh fo tseb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw ,yralC-
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”htworG“ saw sihT
,em tsuj s'ti ,woN
,tas uoy sa woh em dlot uoY
,yks eht ni eseeg eht tuoba em llet d'uoY
,traH ydrA yb uoy ot daer eb lliw meop s’yadoT
,llits tas uoy ,won dekaN
,seenk ruoy ot ylsseldrow nwod delttes uoy sa dnof llits tub
,em llet ,esaelp tub ,gnivaelc dna smoor fo kaeps uoY
,deppots ecnis gnol d'eW  "?gnivael uoy era
.sraey eht revo rehto hcae ot snoitoved yliad ruo erew sklaw esehT
.wen gnihtemos otni degnahc uoy erehw gnissap
,stoor detuorps dna lios eht htaeneb delwarc sregnif ruoY
.snoitome fo bmud
,sdrow fo bmuD .bmud spahrep tub
,riomem a dna slevon ot
,emit tuoba wenk I lla fo thguoht dna stoor ruoy ta tas neht
.tsal ta llits yletelpmoc eb dna enots ot nrut thgim uoy emit eht rof gnitiaw ,enola dna teiuq