.ybraen taob s’norahC ffo gnippets sluos eht erew ecneserp ym ni sruf rehto ylno ehT .lennut pmad
.mih dessap ew sa noitavresbo ot denruter neht
,ysatsce fo seirc
drow rehtona tuohtiW
.thguoht dnoces a tuohtiw suratraT fo ssyba krad eht otni tsac yletaidemmi eb dluow
”?latrom ,eb uoy thgim ohw dnA“
,flow erem siht ta gninworF
”!gnivil eht fo dnal eht ot kcab em dnes tsum uoY“
hcoorb eznorb a emac sehtolc eht htiW
,dedivorp sdoof daednu eht demusnoc ylregae dna
erom ecno mih dessik I
”.stopS ,kcab eb ot doog si tI“
,snoitasnes gnirevihs ,skcab gnihcra
,spil s’rehto hcae otni dehsivar eW
.rehtegot dekcol seye
.drawnwod srae xis sih dedlof eh
esav ybraen a otni wap eerf ym deppid I nehw
.sedaH ot kcab neeuQ rieht gnimoclew teuqnab eht dnetta ot ytinutroppo eht sluos devirra ylwen dna stcejbus ym dewolla I ,shtnom xis yrevE
,sbmil denot dna selppin ylthgirps ’solihP gnileef pots ylerab dluoc sregnif yM
.ecnirp yM .etam devoleb yM
delggurts yeht drah woh rettam oN
.tsehc erab ym ot esolc dna
em rof flesti desiar ydaerla hcihw
,kcalb eht fo dne eht ta thgil mid eht sdrawot deniart ylprahs seye dloc
rettahc fo mhtyhr eht ot ecnelis drawkwa eht gnimuser
”…ssenhgiH ruoY ,seigolopA“
.detnemmoc eh ”,neeuQ“
”,sedaH ni devirra evah eW“                 .solihP
elims gnivol reh htiw railimaf eb dluow slatrom eht ,yllamroN
.htaed dna efil fo ecnalab eht saw ti
,hguoht etsah on detsixe erehT
,neeuQ ym ,gniK yM“
,roloc elbaviecrep yreve htiw nwes symalhc a detfarc neeb dah solihP
,revirnwod deraeppasid taob eht sa noos sA
.tnecs gnirps dna enip sih fo llems eht ta
dehctiwt eson ym ,yllaniF
P“                 ”.lained ni si ohw eno eht era uoY“
.yltfos delims solihP
eciv a ni osrot ym ot gnulc smra siH
,llew…os gnitca wal-ni-rehtom ym fo thgis eht ta naorg ot ton em ni gnihtyreve koot tI
.noissap eno sa detinuer erew ew ,yad tahT
”,sedaH gniK ,deneddas ma I“
yawa gninrut deirt ro dellats ohw yna tub
”,sdog eht fo elur eht dnoyeb era yeht kniht meht fo emoS“
,tsal eht naht tnagavartxe erom eb dluow raey hcaE
,em erofeb gnileenk noil ylredle eht deksa I
rebmahcdeb elbram suoicaps ruo otni solihP gniyrrac dna gnitfil retfA                 .retne ot
.gniggeb doots won eh
.gnol yrev rof ton tub
,nrets dna dloc hguohtlA
selims eslaf rehtie htiw su deteerg
,)selcsum deniart-llew dna htaehs sih ta levram tub pleh t’ndluoc mohw fo lla(
.tsal gnol ta ,devirra rebmetpeS
,sessik dna skcil gnivol
.sroloc tsekrad eht ni detniap kaolc dna
ecnahc lanif eno evah dluow
,em deweiv netfo evah slatrom eht sa
flow gnuoy gnihctiwt
,lennut eht nwod weiv otni emac taob rellams A
,delims yltfos dna em ot pu dekool ylwols neht ,derepmihw eh
,etaf ym tpecca llahs I ,drawretfA
,swaptoof sih no sgniw htiw cinut a ni erah derruf-nworb elbazingocer a
!daed eb tonnac I“
stcejbus gnimoceb erofeb
”,devoleb ym ,uoy dessim evah I“
,delevehsid a saw leenk ot luos txen ehT
.neeuQ ym yb mih ot nevig
noissimrep sserpxe meht evag I sselnu
.em decnivnoc dah reed eht ,noitarebiled elttil retfa dna
tseuqer ylbmuh-h I
”.nevigrof era uoY“                 .dehgual-flah eh
ssenrettib etelpmoC .ssenrettiB
cisum daednu ot decnad slatrom nellaf eht sA
,uoy dessim evah I hcum woh ebircsed tonnac llits sdrow tub“ ,I did sa
yawa ssem gnilwoh eht gard ot dedeecorp dnuoh dedaeh-eerht eht ,drawrof gnikluH
.yllautneve eid tsum lla ruf latrom yreve tub ,leurc si tI“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.rehtegot gnipsalc swap ruo
hcraM ecnis edaf ot nugeb d’taht evol fo kraps eht
!od ot hcum os evah I
.dlrowrednu eht fo ssenmid eht ni enihs ot demees taht derewolf ni deniadro riah reh
,stsevrah rieht desselb ehs sa ecarg dnik dna
,ylduorp dewob surebreC ”,solihP neeuQ ,emoh emocleW“
,ydob dekan sih gnola ruf kcalb cillatem fo desopmoc dna thgieh ni sretem owt ta gnidnatS
.setag dnomaid eht ot
noitamih a htaeneb eceip tsehc muimso ym erow I ,yllamroN
enim sa dloc sa seye sih
:solihP & sedaH“
sdraug ruatnec yb del gnieb ylnellus elihw
”.sthgis ruo morf latrom hsiloof taht devomer uoy dalg ylpmis ma I“
”.uoy ekilnu ,tcepser dah eH“
niamod ym deretne ohw slatrom desaeced yltnecer eht lla dna
!uoy fo geb I ,esaelP-
,kcab solihP emoclew dna sevlesmeht ecudortni dluow drawrof pets ot hguone dlob esohT
.tneitapmi em edam dah shtnom eht wenk yehT
”!ecno ta degduj eb ot soniM ot mih gnirB“
,doof dna gnicnad eht neewteB
.rehtegot raey a flah dessessop won ew ecnis
.retlaf ton did eh ”,dnatsrednu od I“
,dnabsuh yM .neeuQ ym saw
ro noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
htaenrednu kcub gnuoy a gnilaever
.xytS reviR eht fo lennut eht ot spmopohcysp ym fo eno dewollof ylippah enilef eht
.noisserpxe tnerruc reh was meht fo enon tub
”.ecnirP yM ,emoh kcab emocleW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dehgual reed retrohs ehT
,sruoh rof derolpxe eW
,erow dnabsuh ym sserd eht yawa gnileep yletaciled fo ronoh launna eht deniatbo I
.srebmahc dna snrevac tsav eht revo demool taht ecalap gnirewot eht ssim ton dluow latrom a
nworc a sa seilil dna sesor fo htaerw rewolf a detrops ylduorp osla dal ehT
sruoh sseltnuoc ekil tlef tahw tneps I ,ecnartne eht tA
***   .staebtraeh ruo fo sdnuos lufrednow eht tsdima peels su tel dna
,namyrref etutitsbus eht
”…semreH ,’neeuQ‘ si ti taht uoy gnidnimer peek I“
,rehto hcae ot deliart seye ruo nehW
”!slatrom ,sedaH fo mlaer eht ot emocleW“
deid neht dna devil slatrom
H“ .eye sih ni eralg etarepsed a htiw
,luos rieht fo stip eht otni gid seye ybur ’surebreC ssentiw dluow
erusaelp lautum ruo ni dam em gnivirD
,htaed epacse nac luos on taht dootsrednu eH“
ebor tevlev a etaerc ot sroliat eht denoissimmoc I ,thginot rof teY
.cisum daednu dna
”,stopS ,rof ezigolopa ot gnihton si erehT“                 ”.htaed fo
,teknalb eceelf a ekil sgel ruo dnuora liat ym gnilruC
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,rewot tsellat eht fo esab eht ta
”.htaed dna efil fo ecnalab eht si tI
,sraet lufitip yrc ro riapsed ton oD“
gniretne latrom a no desucof
.daed eht fo revir eht ssorca meht dediug namyrref lateleks a sa
erimda ot pu sdaeh rieht detfil ylneddus erofeb morf sluos ehT
ecidrawoc sih sdrawot
.etanargemop der doolb a fo epahs eht ni
dnik eb ton lliw soniM taht uoy esimorp I“
”!?em ton yhw os ,og tac taht tel uoY-Y
,deb klis ruo tsniaga kcab sih detser solihP ,retaL
.swap koohs yllamrof yehT
.su erofeb
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.gnivil etarbelec ot
,ecnatculer emos htiw decnuonna ,deilper I ”.llew yreV“
:yojne esaelP    .trAtnaiveD
.su morf srovaf ksa ylpmis ro su esiarp
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.oot elkcuhc tub pleh t’ndluoc I dna
tnemom suoegrog taht ni derised I llA
.evol ekam dluow I dna reed der emosdnah eht
”…em ecalp ot ediced uoy reverehw-w
.ti hcuot solihP leef ot dehca llits—’supairP sa evisserpmi sa ton hguoht—eniM
.keehc sih elzzun ot nwod denael I
,revewoh devoleb ym saw reh ediseb gnittiS                 .em ta detcerid
pihsnamstfarc enivid eht ta niaga ecno levram tub pleh ton dluoc I
,edisni gnidael draytruoc dna snedrag eht tsap deklaw eno fi tub
.sreltna sih htaeneb
,noitcif raluger dna yrruf etirw ot sevol ohw
,su teerg ot pu enil dluow slatrom
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,sesserac eltneg hguorht detalsnart eb ylno dluoc taht artsehcro na otni su gnilluP
.swam eerht sih morf gnittips eriflleh yrgna eht sa llew sa
.hguoht ecneserp ym egdelwonkca ot derad meht fo enoN
,thgiled gniredduhs
,ecnatsid a morf laoc sa roloc emas eht demees tI
.ecnartne gnipolevne sih daerps doohnam ym sa
”!namow lufituaeb a truoc ot gniyrt elihw debbor saw I !ereh eb t’nac I
drawrof denael eW                 ”.dnabsuh raed ym
”.emitefil a detsaw yeht esuaceb regnol evil ot deltitne ylpmis era yeht eveileb yehT“
”solihP & sedaH fo edulerP eht“
,taob eht ffo dnabsuh ym depleh dna kcod eht ot revo deklaw I
.ecno ylno reh tisiv ot dewolla eb I
ylthgils deruos erofeb morf ssenippah regae ehT
.tserof tiliwt a dehctam taht
”.uoy tuohtiw raey gnol a neeb sah tI“
.kcod etavirp eht ediseb taob rieht dewols
.ybraen dekrab seciov gnimoob eerht
”!ecalp dirroh siht morf eelf em tel lliw uoY
,deyevnoc eb ot dedeen sdrow oN
”,ecnelosni sih rof ezigolopa I
sroloc neerg dna elprup fo desopmoc
”,suhcoriepyH ,uoy ot sgniteerG“
pu doots reed der ehT
hcaorppa ot hguone evarb luos ynA
,yllaciotS .ylrehtom
solihP elihw llA
.tnecs ylhtrae ym htiw gnixim redneval dna
.senorht ynobe dna yrovi ruo morf teuqnab eht gnivresbo
,tniartser tuohtiw kcen sih delbbin I
)rufdaeh ym pota revlis erup fo edam saw enim(
”edulerP :solihP & sedaH“
.evoba ot denruter eb ot gniksa rof tnaem ti fi reven tub
,sicoV sumoD ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb ”edulerP
,noitasrevnoc tnelis a degnahcxe I dna solihP
.esiar ot denraey syawla retemeD
,kcen sih no delbbin I elihw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,dlrowrednU eht otni gnidael
.devoleb ym rof gnitiaw
,dnabsuh yM                 .neeuq yM
.erom ecno mih derewolfed I sa steehs eht gnippirg
,nosinu ni ekops sdaeh eerht siH
ecalkcen elpmis a ylno erow surebreC
.dennalp sa drawno eunitnoc dluow teuqnab ehT
sdog lla fo wenk I
.mih ediseb reed redle eht degguh yltpmorp dna
,xytS reviR eht fo serohs eht ta doots I sa
!kcab og ot deen I“ .denihw eh ”!kcab og em tel tsum uoy ,sedaH-
sicoV sumoD yb
.’pots reven esaelp‘ fo sgnirettum dehctih lareves dna ’uoy evol I‘ lufraet a
,tsehc mraw sih gnola dessik I sa demriuqs ydob elppus esohw
,em rof ekops solihP
si yrots s’yadot dna
”,sedaH ,depleh eb tonnac tI“
.doohnam detcelgen sih gnikorts
”…rehtoM ,shtnom xis ni uoy eeS“
.su gnidnuorrus sksum eht gnilahni elihw seitilauxes tcere dna seidob detaeh ruo gnisserac
.mih otni spih delcsum ym tsurht I emit hcae stnurg ym htiw desurohc
,ytinrete na ekil tlef tahw rof smra ym ni nam gnuoy eht dleh ylpmis I ,yawa gnitraP
.yawyna mih dlot I tub
niar hserf fo desopmoc siH
,srae sih otni derepsihw I
,setaf lanif rieht yfed ot deirt ro
em deknalf seiprah deromra yllufituaeb owT
.retpecs nori ym gnippirg
tlenk dna denruter surebreC erofeb su esiarp ot pu enil sluos lareveS
.mih llits saw ti
,deifingid tas I dna solihP
”—ot hsiw uoy fI .uoy ekilnu
,seireuq rieht raeh ot degilbo eb d’ew ,semitemoS
saw sihT.sedaH fo
”,enO suelubuE ,suhcoriepyH-
.em htiw seye dekcol relevart tsedle eht nehw
.ylthgit wap ym dleh
,dlrowrednU eht fo neeuQ dna gniK taerG ,hO““
,dias solihP ekiL
.devom eh emit hcae deremmihs taht gninil eulb thgindim a dna
.erom ecno lennut krad eht nwod tfird ot nageb dna kcod eht morf yawa dellup semreH—
ylgnivol reed ehtil eht gnidloh
.eb dluoc evol eurt lufrewop woh
sreltna demmirt dna llams fo riap a ylno deirrac ro
,skeehc eerht sih ssorca ylthgil dehsulb neve surebreC
.spil s’rehto eht otni detlem dna
rehtegot deniwtne yal I dna solihP ,wolgretfa latrommi ruo nI                 .sore enO
.kcab meht eracs ot hguone syawla saw enola tahT
”.rethguad suoicerp ym ,uoy ssim lliw I“
.lio egassam mraw fo
.dnuoh ralucsum eht ta nwod delims solihP
ti gnihcaer reve tuohtiw ytinrete rof klaw ylno dluow
,rehtom sih ot sknaht
,liat pordraet sih htaeneb aera eht enola tel
.ybraen mih dednammoc I ”!surebreC“
tlusni ro snoitpursid desuac ohw esohT
,gniK rieht ediseb gniklaw neeuQ rieht ta
”…retemeD morf traped tsum uoy yrros ma I“
,draytruoc ecalap eht fo tuo
.htmraw tnaidar ruo ni
.latrom siht ta nwod derats ew sa
.erom ecno trapa shtnom xis rehtona tneps gnivah
,sesserd neerg fo tsethgirb eht gniraew eod derruf-der lufituaeb a saw ehS
.elzzum deyerg sih desiar ylsuovren eh
.derised tsevraH eht dna ytilitreF fo sseddoG eht tahw rettam ton did ti ,revewoH
.enorht ym ni delbmurg I
”.solihP ,uoy evol I“
fo edam eb ot ecalap eht wonk dluow yeht
sserd etihw-wons a erow eh fi rettam ton did tI .worg ot nageb
”…gniK yM .sedaH ,uoy evol I dnA“
.ero naidisbo gninihs dna yrevlis
”.latrom ,daed era uoY“
.mlaer ym fo ssenkrad eht nethgirb dluoc enola elims siH
gnittis sregnessap owt htiw
nediam eod eht ot desoppo sa
.roolf dehsilop eht no denroda yal yeht litnu gnihtolc ruo ta gnillup elihw sksum ruo gnilahni
!dnatsrednu tsum uoY“ .neeuQ yM
”.worromot nwad yb swodaeM ledohpsA eht ot denruter eb lliw uoy neht tub ,thginot tsuj rof reh tisiv ot dewolla eb lliw uoY“
.lufhtuoy deniamer gninrom eht hguoht neve
”!neeuQ dna gniK ruo fo
,ylohcnalem ro suovren regnol oN
H si eman yM-M“                 ”.pu kaepS“
.mih dniheb gnihsiws liat depahs-worra sih
ecalap ym ni emoclewnu esoht ,revewoH
,etaf sih detpecca dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sezag gnidaelp ro
.yoj ym detarogivnier taht dna
.smra reh ni ylthgit mih dleh retemeD
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
sdaeh eerht s’dnuohlleh eht fo hcaE
.htaed erofeb emit lanif a reh devol I efiw ym llet ot elba reven saw I
.ylnmelos detats dnabsuh ym
.edis ym yb reed der eht rof yllaicepse
,su dedivorp sroliat ym
.eralg yldaed s’retemeD fo erawa ylluf
”!daed eb tonnac I
su neewteb don truc a hguoht—
,tneitapmi su edam ,rehtar rO
,”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“ levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
snaom hsiyob dna seirc s’reed eht
drawnwod sliat dna selzzum ,srae suoirav rieht tpek yllufraef yeht ,daetsnI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb
setag dnomaid eht tsaP
”!sedaH ,esaelP“                 ”—seitivitsef eht yojnE“ ,deilper I
stcejbus layol eht won era uoy rof
.solihP ym morf htgnel s’mra ta ylno saw eh litnu drawrof depmots eH