.snoitidart ylimaf eht dessim ydaerla ehS
t’nerA“  .sooragnak ekil kool ot deci dna tuc
.strohs reh fo sessecer eht otni
.em ot eno tuohtiw samtsirhC ekil leef t’nseoD
”.hcnul samtsirhC gnikam s’ehS .s’yaK ta m’I“
”.noon neve ton s’tI ?reeB“ ”.flesruoy pleh ot emoclew er’uoY
,tsaot hcnerF yna teg t’ndid I ,toh oot s’tI
,sgniw ecal dna nwog etihw a ni desserd
.retaw dloc eci fo knird a rof nam a llik ylbaborp dluoc ehs taht deredisnoc ylfeirb ehs
”.uoy tuohtiw emas eht ton s’tI
.erofeb semit lareves enod dah ti sa
.daeh reh no tah atnas yzzuf dna
”.retteb tol a leef I .emac I dalg m’I
stiucsib fo xob eht decnalab ehS
.neeb reve dah ehs tseippah eht saw tI
,noitasnednoc htiw deppird wodniw sub ehT .sllab sa
.ffo koot ti sa sub eht sa duol sa tsomla
.etivni eht ot gnidrocca
.ereh nwod teg t’ndluoc uoy emahs laer a s’tI“
.rehtegot samtsirhC evah syawla eW .samtsirhC rof ereh nwod emoc t’nac uoy yhw ees t’nod tsuj I
”.su htiw ereh emoclew syawla er’uoY“
detaroced ylgnivol neeb llits dah ti
.enif m’I ,haey ,sey ,hO“
,desimorp ehs ekil
.gninworf dna tsehc ralucsum reh revo smra reh gnissorc ,dias yaK
”.yaK ,samtsirhC yrreM“
”.yllaer ,toh tsuj m’I
”?niaga daD ruoy ti sI“
.liat suoreneg reh dniheb hcaer ot desuap ehS ”…tuB
.elzzum reh otni taem eht devohs dna delims adniL
.epat fo llor a flah ekil dekool tahw htiw ecalp ni dleh
”.rehtona gniyas s’liat ruoy tub ,gniht eno gniyas s’elzzum ruoY“
htworg eert kciht ni derevoc
.etavilas ot detrats yletaidemmi dna
,snwarp eht dehsinif ehS
,mah eht yltsom htiw
.nwod emoc evah dluoc llits uoY“
.elbat eht ta ecalp cilobmys a gnireffo yb reh devol llits yeht wonk reh gnittel
.riahc reh ot kcab gninruter erofeb
,ssenihtlaeh fo redro gnidnecsed ni pu denil erew
sessalg rieht dehcuot yehT
.snwarp fo elip a dna ,dalas otatop
taf detsurc ezalg fo eceip a sa eugnot reh revo daerps ssenteews ekil elcaert ,krad A
,elbat eht nioj ot tey erew stiucsib s’adniL
.htiw pu peek ot aremac eht rof kciuq oot tnemevom eht
.ton ro esigolopa ot dedeen ehs fi ediced ot gniyrt emitrevo gnikrow niarb reh
.sreeb dna sredic ,seitfos htiw kcab tuo ykse na tog eW“
.ytrap s’dneirf reh rof doog oot saw ehs ekiL .euqebrab a tsuJ
”.denigami evah dluoc I naht esrow hcum osla wohemos tub ,thguoht I sa dab sa toN“
.sub denoitidnoc ria eht fo llihc lufrednow eht fo yromem eht neve gniyortsed yltnatsni
.smra reh dessorc ooragnak ehT
.lla retfa suoiciled llits erew yehT
noitidnoc tnerruc stI
.yad eht fo ytidimuh eht yawa gnitaeb ylwols
?em ta nworht ev’uoy gnimahs tliug taht lla htiw leef em gnikam neeb ev’uoy yttihs woh aedi yna evah uoy oD
”.retal uoy ot taht evig ot gniog saw I“
.tiucsib eht dehsinif yaK
,)elbissop sehtolc naiiawah suolucidir tsom ,tsethgirb eht gniraew no detsisni ohw ,naD elcnU rof tpecxe(
.esnopser ni wap a devaw tsuj ohw revird sub eht ot dellac ehs
.tuo tsehc reh gniffup ,dias yaK
.redluohs reh revo ekops dna denrut yaK
.reniatnoc citsalp a laever ot repap gnipparw eht nepo deppir ooragnak ehT
.stneserp rof emit tcefrep eht si woN“ .dehgual tsuj yaK
.txen emac tahw dedaerd ehs dna
.seirrehc ynihs fo lwob a ot txen tas skeehc ognam citamora dna elppaenip
,sgnul eht sllif taht shgis peed esoht fo enO
;sdrow eht ton tub seciov
gnikil reh rof dratsum hcum oot elttil a htiw
,ekil eb dluoc daD reh tahw wenk ehS
.lanif saw ti dias d’eh yaw ehT
.ylkaew delims adniL
.ereh devil syawla ev’eW
,esruoc fo ,snwarp dnA
.edis eno ot poord gniht eritne eht gnikam
.woleb dessap ehs nehw smaercs evissergga otni nrut dluow selbraw eltneg ’seipgam
niatnuom ediw a ,meht dnoyeB
.delims dna deddon daD
”.eraf ria eht flah diap evah dluoc eW
.ecnef ot ecnef morf meht htaeneb gnihcterts nwal ylggarcs ,wolley a htiw
,thgil noitasrevnoc eht peek ot etarepsed
.sgniw nekcihc dna sgans gnilzzis llits fo yart liof A
,sriahc gnipmac tuo dlof fo retsulc A
tisiV‘ .thgit dehcnelc waj s’adniL
,’samtsirhC yrreM‘ oN ?naem ti did tahW
.tsrif uoy rof eseht edam I“
.ti ekops ehs sa noos sa ”tsuj“ drow eht detterger ehS
.gniruop detrats dna nepo ti dekcarc
”.inU hsinif ot enuJ ni pu devom I .ainamsaT
.daD morf txet a saw
”?ti no eman ym evah ti seod“
.enohp reh ta lrans ot tuoba flesreh thguac ehs dna hteet gnilaever
enohp eht dnuora pirg s’adniL
no emoC“ .elttob eht ta gab eht ni gnikeep
.tsrif meht netae d’ehs dehsiw ehs won tuB
.kcab tuo s’enoyrevE .ni
.niatrec dna tnedifnoc
.lausac oot yaw demees tI
.emoh kcab did yeht sa doog sa gnitsat esle erehwyna morf snwarp enigami t’ndluoc adniL
,sratiug dlo dna stcejorp tehcorc denodnaba
htiw dednopser dah yeht
.taht yas reven dluow ehs tub
,ecuas elppa dna yrrebnarc
?aelp a ti saw rO ?yrgna yeht ereW ?dnamed A
,lewot tew a ekil ydob s’adniL otni deppals taeH
.dluoc kcoL spaC yna naht reduol demaercs taht pots-lluf a dna sdrow elttil eerhT
.stipmra reh rednu ruf eht ni ssenikcits etaidemmi na tlef ehs dna
.stneve laicos ta pu wohs ot tsrif eht gnieb detah adniL sa ,doog saw hcihw
.sgniht reh detcelloc adniL dna
.knip thgirb a denrut srae s’daD fo edisni ehT
,seilf wef a yawa gnittawS
llehs dna daeh eht devomer adniL
enilno elpoep lufrednow ynam os tem d’ehS
osaM deman raob tliub ylkciht a ,yllanif dnA
.renroc eht ni doots eert samtsirhc citsalp A
,yadiloh emos t’nsaw sihT ’?sdneirf
.erom ffo uoy ssip tsuj ll’tI
,tuo dellac dna denrut ehs nehT
.emas eht yats syawla t’nod sgnihT .daD ,segnahc tihS“
.nur ertemolik thgie na neeb evah llew sa yam ti tub
.yenom on evah I dna yaD samtsirhC yllaretil s’tI“
woble reh fo koorc eht ni
,enabsirB ni samtsirhC tsrif reh saw tI
,stiucsib nezod a erew edisnI
,lluks s’adniL fo esab eht ta detrats zzub wolloh A
,strohs draob egnaro thgirb
tsaerb yekrut dloc fo secilS
.kcul fo tuo eb thgim uoy neht
”.ot tnaw t’nod yllaer osla I tub
.rettort sih morf gnilgnad X ruoF fo ybbuts a
.nwotemoh reh ni dnif ot mees t’ndluoc tsuj ehs taht snoitcennoc gnorts fo dnik eht edam dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
ooragnak egral a dna
”?eh t’nsi siht tuoba erutammi yrev gnieb s’eH“
.taeh fo dnik siht ot desu t’nsaw llits ehS
.pu ekops ylneddus
,nehctik eht ta pu decnalg yaK ”…eseht
.shtaerb prahs ni gnihtaerb detrats adniL
”.uoy tuohtiw emas eht eb t’now tI“
.tneserp deruoloc dlog dna etihw
eerht tsuJ ’.uoy evol‘ on ,’olleh‘ on
.daeh reh koohs yaK
.tas stiucsib fo xob rehto s’adniL erehw
”?enalp a kcajih dna won thgir tropria eht ot nuR
.hcum os uoy ssim I ,yteewS“
.woh wonk t’ndid ehS
.yerg krad a otni edaf ot detrats dah selzzum rieht dnuora ruf kcalb eht tub
.meht revo gnitfird sdneirf fo rebbaj eht
enohp reh no segami fo tsrub desufnoc a gnihctaw
.derewsna yaK ”,edalamraM“
.pu snoitaroced samtsirhC eht htiw depmarc erom neve saw
,ot tnaem ehs naht rekciuq
.denethgirb ecaf reH ”.wonk t’nod I
”?pukcab deen annog uoY“ ”.yaK sknahT“
,slamina yhtlif uoy yakO“
tfig depparw yldab eht koot adniL
”.seno tnrub wef a dna ,hguod revotfel era srehto ehT“ .adniL dias
.elpmis taht yllaer s’tI
”!mah samtsirhC suomaf yM“  ”?gnikooc s’tahW“
.oga sraey wef a enilno epicer eht dnuoF“
.sfoor delit der fo sehsalf kciuq hguorht gnittel
elims a evag tar eht sugnA
”.enasni ydoolb s’ti ,elfirt fo lwob eguh a thguorb sugnA dnA
,gnisimorp erom erew stcepsorp kroW
.trid eht otni gniggid tsomla
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,sdnuos laudividni no sucof ot gniyrt
htaerb peed a koot ehS
.ytiniffA ruF no ro ,golb sih no sgnitirw sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
repap knip thgirb fo elddaws a dehctulc ti
.tuo esoht denword ecived eht tsniaga gnikcalc swalc llud
,ruf reh morf sgep s’relbboc gnikahs sa ysae sa tuoba saw daeh reh morf yromem eht gnikahS
.dnim reh morf thgiew sti fo emos tsuj gnitfil ylohcnalem eht
.relooc seerged evlewt tuoba ti dekil osla ehS
...egdirf eht ni og ot sdeen taht gnihtyna evah uoy fI
.snwarp hserf eht noitnem ot toN
?ereht pu gnihtyreve si woH
,dehcaorppa sllaftoof yvaeh fo gnipmuht ehT .dekconk ehS
:hcnul eht fo noipmahc detupsidnu eht tas
,sneppah revetahw tub
”.taht ekil em ot klat ton oD“ .dekrab eh ”!adniL“
.daD otni esnes emos klat dluoc muM ebyam tuB
.gnorw reh evorp yllausu dluow
,ssarg wolley eht tsniaga detsiwt teef reH
”!tihs fo eceip sselhtrow a ekil leef em gnikam s’ti dna
.erofeb tekcit enalp eht fo trap yna yap ot dereffo reven dah daD
;olleh elpmis dna
,pu til eugnot reH
”.tohs a htrow s’tI
”?thgiarts os gnici eht teg uoy d’woH“
,reh gniretsep pots dluow daD fi retteb tol a fo lleh a eb dluow gnihtyrevE
.ria eht ta deffins dna nehctik eht hguorht yaK dewollof adniL
.elcsum fo hctiwt a ylerab
,eugnot reh revo dehsaw ssenihtrae dna surtiC
.yltfos dias adniL ”,si eh ,haeY“
edistuo eht t’nsaw ti
,nwo reh no edam d’ehs noisiced lufgninaem dna tnenamrep a t’nsaw ti ekil
.dehcaorppa rebmeceD sa deniarts ylgnisaercni emaceb stnerap reh ot sllac enohp raluger ehT
”.yadot yllaicepsE
mah dezalg fo secils eht pu gniyvvid daD dna
,gab eht fo tuo elttob s’adniL dellup ehS ”!od ew tiaw hO
.retal sdalas rehto eht rof kcab og d’ehS
.eson reh dehctiwt yaK .knard dna
,stiucsib samtsirhC deci-dnah fo lluf reniatnoc erawrepput a ta dehctulc swap s’adniL
?woH !yciuj os saw tI
.deil ehs ”,enif s’gnihtyrevE“
dellems dna moolb lluf ni saw tI
,sdnoces lareves rof pu deggof
.mah a od syawla I“
.esnes yna edam taht fi
,releeh eulb delkceps etihw dna kcalb a ,adniL
.niaga dlrow edistuo eht htiw tcaretni ot saw ti taht
,yaK dias ”!samtsirhC yrreM !lrig ,yeH“
.hguoht traboH ylnO
.stnerap reh erew yehT
.ylimaf morf yawa tsrif reh ,yltnatropmi erom dna
,ymaerc dna tfos erew seotatop ehT
.taeh eht ni relooc meht peek ot
”.samtsirhC yrreM ,daD ih ,muM iH“
.repap dexaw eht fo ytirgetni larutcurts eht esimorpmoc ot doof hguone htiw demmarc neht dna
?won siht yas eh dluow yhW
.won thgir meht etah osla I tub ylimaf ym ssim I ,tnemtrapa egabrag ym rof snoitaroced yna droffa t’nac I
.mool ot detrats nosaes yadiloh eht nehT
tnecs eht fo ffihw a thguac adniL
.saw ti lufituaeb woh no sucof ot deirt dna niatnuom eht ta wodniw eht hguorht derats
.yromem ot ti gnittimmoc
.emoh a ti edam taht edisni elpoep eht tub
.reh htiw tnarodoed fo nac a thguorb d’ehs dehsiw ehS
,evom eht edam dah adniL
.gnol oot yaw rof neercs eht ta derats adniL
”.uoy ees ot dooG .vul ,yad’G“
.liob doolb reh edam
.noitativni ytrap eht sa delbuod taht tahc puorg eht no setadpu yna rof dekcehc ehS
.wenk ydaerla ehs keeg ertaeht wollef a ,tibbar eht kcirE
.nom’C .ydaer si hcnuL“
.delaeuqs tsomla neht dna tnemom a rof dewehc ehS
,ekih erutarepmet neddus eht ta rorroh dengiser ni erows ehS
.ot detnaw eh nehw suoivilbo eb dluoc daD
.egassem a saw tI
meht neewteb egassem tsal ehT  .meht devol ehS
.rettug tnorf eht nwod raet ot denetaerht dna
.gnihton dedeen mah siht tub
.adniL naht flesreh ot erom ,muM dias
,snikpan ycnaf dna setalp doog eht htiw thgie rof tes elbaT
.gniod saw ehs tahw detneser reh fo trap ynit A
.ti fo dne eht saw taht
.doow fo spihc lareves htiw gnola ,yawa tniap eht fo hcum deppirts dah rehtaew fo sedaced tub
ylbakatsimnu saw tahw gnidloh dna
.enohp reh gnizeeuqs saw ehs desilaer adniL
,aedi on dah ehs meht dlot yllufhturt ehs nehW
”.thgir er’uoy kniht I taht etah I“
.egdirf s’yaK fo egufer looc eht ni stressed rehto eht htiw tiaw ni gniyal
,daetsni muM ot klat ot tog ehs noisacco erar eht nO
.hgis a tuo tel adniL
.trohs lla fo tsom dna ,elpmis
.nepo dessih rood edis ehT
.dnuora gnitrad seye ,delbmum ehs ”,yrros m’I“
,euqebrab a saw ytrap sihT
,sehcnip elttil ekil emac
ni deyats d’ehs esuoh rednalsneeuQ yreve sa
,ognid legna tlef a tas pot yrev eht tA
,yawa tneserp eht dehctans adniL
,sriahc rieht otni dexaler yeht nehT
.samtsirhC rof emoh kcab ylf ot evol dluow adniL ,yllufhturT
stnerap reh draeh ehS .rekaeps ynnit emas eht morf emac esion taht lla nehw desufnoc deyats tub
”?gnorw s’tahw ,yeH“
,daeh reh koohs ehS
,yletarucca erom ro
”,eno mih tleb ydoolb dluoc I ,yllaeR“
tsom eht no pmop fo tib a dekil ehS
,tsafkaerb rof tsaot hcnerF
”.llew yrev ti htiw gnilaed ton tsuj s’eh esoppus I
.s’ooragnak eht ot detfird wap s’adniL
?gniog gnihtyreve si woh ,adniL“
.sllehs rieht ni egnaro thgirb
,erbilac taht fo sesuoh lla htiw sa tub
.prahs enin ta egnahcxe tneserp eht yb dewollof
.rehtaew siht ni snaej ynniks kcalb gniraew saw eh woh aedi on dah adniL
”?tey meht dellac uoy evaH“ .dehgis adniL
”.daD ruoy htiw sdrow ’a elpuoc a gnivah dnim t’ndluow I“
!tey inU dehsinif t’nevah I esuaceb ,boj tneced a evah t’nod I esuaceb ,yenom yna evah t’nod I esuaceb ,won thgir ti droffa t’nac I .od os I ,od I tub ,kcab emoc ot tnaw t’nod I ekil tca uoY
,dratsum fo stop elttil yb dednuorruS
,yrros os m’I .yteews hO“
.rof ylsuoixna tiaw ot llac rehtona taerG
”.og sgniht woh tsuj s’taht semitemos
”?os kniht yllaer uoY“ .dehgis adniL
”.yrellag tra gnizamA .enecs gniknird tneceD
,eert ognam a fo sevael eht hguorht gniretlif nus toh eht fo elddim eht ni nezorf
,ssalg eniw a dleh taht xob draobdrac a saw edisnI
krowecittal tnorf eht pu werg taht
.dehtaerb adniL ”,ecitcarP“
”,werdnA
,suoegrog saw daor nabrubus ralucitrap siht morf weiv ehT
”.ecnis stnialpmoc yna dah t’nevaH
taht ni suoiruc tsuj erew yeht demussa adniL
.yad lla uoy ta tae ot gniog si siht esiwrehtO
.elzzum s’adniL ot elims ynit eht kcab thguorb noitamriffa ehT
.detpurretni d’ehs noitasrevnoc revetahw morf yawa delffuhs dna
?meht llac ot evah ehs did yhW
.uoy sessim dna ,uoy sevol eH
”?samtsirhC enabsirB tsrif ruoy gniyojne uoy era woH“
”.aedi trams a t’nsaw ereht pu gnivoM“
,nom’C“ ”.yaK ,sknahT“
.adniL dias ”,yssalC“
,dalas hcae fo lufnoops a detcelloc osla ehS
.hcum os uoy gnittespu erew ew esilaer t’ndid I
.elims delffum a hguorht deksa ehs ”?taht si tahW“
.nwo sti no lla ti did tI
,tuo dednah erew setalp repap dna skrof citsalP
yzarc ekil gnitnap saw adniL ,esuoh eht fo yawevird eht pu deklaw ehs emit eht yB
.sekorts trohs ni evom ot detrats liat s’adniL
.enod syawla ev’ew ekil ylimaf a sa samtsirhC evah ot su tnaw tsuj I“
.egassem tnecer tsom eht ooragnak eht dewohs adniL ,gnilbmert llitS
,esuoh eht fo emarf nedoow eritne eht gnikahs tsomla
.niaga ti daer t’noD
stxet dna sllac ehT
,kciht fo lufgnul a ni dehtaerb ehS
”.hguoht def lla su peek ot eibrab eht rof llew sa nekcihc dna sgans fo hcnub a tog ev’I
,seigolohtna yrruf lareves ni dehsilbup seirots trohs sah ohw ,kcilliK yb ”maH“
.emoh ta did ti ekil tsuj detsat tI
,esaelp ,enolA“ ,yas muM draeh adniL ,yllautnevE
,rebmit ,elyts rednalsneeuQ dlo na saw esuoh ehT
.hguoht dereggub ’nikcuF .dab ton ,haeY“ ”?uoy era woH .thgirla gniod m’I“
”maH“   :yojne esaelP
”?euqebrab a tsuj saw ti thguoht I“
deppots sub ehT  .elttil a tsuj
”?su tespu ot gniyrt uoy era yhW“
,skoobtxet htiw dekcap yllausu ,moor gnivil ehT
dnim s’adniL ni oS
,yaw fo dnik latnerap
.rehto yna sa toh sa tsuj tog
”.lrig ,kcab ruoy tog I
”.uoy ekil tsuJ“ ”.lufituaeb s’tI“
.tey noon neve t’nsaw tI
?yaD samtsirhC no tub
,dednopser yaK ”,yhw nehT“
.taht od ll’sdneirf dnA“ .dekrims yaK
.erahs ot thguorb neeb dah taht sreniatnoc erawrepput dna setalp depparw-dalg suoirav eht yb nwod dehgiew
.llufkrof suoitibma s’adniL ta
,seno dnuor gib ,sessalg reH
.sserts ot ton adniL dlot ehs
,tah hcuols kroc lacipytoerets a
.sgel reh neewteb liat reh htiw won yad yna emoh yrrucs ot desoppus saw ehs ekil
.esaelp su llaC  .daD morF
,devirra dah s’yaK fo sdneirf eroM
,devirra ydaerla ro yaw rieht no gnieb sa detroper dah sdneirf wef A
pu kcab emac wap reh nehW
.raey eht fo yad lufrednow
,ton ro dluohs uoy rehtehw uoy llet ot gniog ton m’I .ti teg I“
.wap reh ni tnelis tnew enohp ehT
.elzzum reh otni hself eht deppop neht
.prahs dna trohs eman eht dias muM
”!werdnA“ ”-I ,vuL ,won toN“
,ylduol derruls osaM
.eciton ot mees t’ndid yaK ,revewoH
eniw fo elttob a deniatnoc taht gab shtrowlooW citsalp a dna
”.adniL ,samtsirhC yrreM“
”.dluohs uoy taht kniht ot mih fo hsifles s’ti dna
”,ylno uoy dna uoy rof er’yehT
rats dlog dna ssalg tnagele eht morf yrc raf A
eciv dewalc a otni denrut enohp reh dnuora pirg luferac s’adniL ”.esaelp ,erutuf eht ni deraperp erom eb ot yrt tsuJ“
”-rof elbirret leef em ekam ot dewolla er’uoy tub ’kcuf‘ yas ot dewolla ton m’I“
.deppans reh edisni gnihtemos sa
.ssalg eht dehsinif dna ,dehgual adniL
.flesreh llems dluoc ehs dna
,mraw dna tfos leef adniL edam syawla ooragnak ehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”!uoy tuoba siht gnikam potS …I“
,ssenpaehc gnitaidar dna llat teef ruof ylnO
,slexip thgirb eht gnisylana
”snoitidart gnikaerb er’uoY“
”.ti dehsaw ydaerla I ,yrrow t’noD“
.yad samtsirhC no yrgna eb ot saw detnaw ehs gniht tsal ehT
,ruovalf ynirb eht hguorht tuc ot ecuas elppa ro yrrebnarc fo lufnoops doog a dedeen mah s’daD reH
.knits nwo reh fo elttil a ksam osla dluow ti yllufepoH .lufrednow
.siht ekil uoy ees ot etah I .dluohs uoY“
,ruovalf eht ot no gnah htuom reh tel dna tas tsuj neht
”.retteb leef uoy pleh ll’deef doog A
.luftbuod erew stnerap reh tsrif tA
,tnasaelp llac siht peek ot detnaw ehs ,sediseB
”.neht seirrow oN“ ”.thgir eb ll’I“
,eert citsalp eht rof yvaeh oot hcum saw tI .BV fo nac a
,stnemevom esicerp ,etaciled htiw
”!devres yllaiciffo si hcnul
”.taht htiw laed ot gniog m’I woh aedi on evah I
,t’nsaw ti ytlas woh yb desirprus yrev saw ehs dnA
,seog gniyas eht ekil
”.eniw emos dna stiucsib thguorb I
,reh rof gnitiaw saw yaK
.seidoog fo gab dna reniatnoc citsalp eht gnicnalab llits elihw
.draykcab eht ot esuoh eht morf spets eht dednecsed yaK dna adniL sa ”!saaaamtsirhC yrreM“
?redro na ti saW .sdrow
.noziroh eht detanimod
,adniL ta yltnatcepxe dekool ehS ”?ti si woH“
.yzzaT ot neeb ev’I“ .sugnA dias ”,emosewa s’tahT“
.secirp samtsirhC ta tekcit enalp a flah neve droffa ot elba neeb evah ton dluow llits ehs
.niaga tuo sehsur lla ti nehw noitcafsitas fo gnileef a gnivael
.enohp reh otni derats ehS
.emit emos etiuq rof nalp eht neeb dah
”?owt ro yad a ni spahreP
,klis ekil meht dnuora depparw tI
,kcalb eht fo gniparcs ytfeh a teg ot erus gnikam
.redro na gnieb tuohtiw dnamed A
”.won thgir enalp a no teg ot uoy redro yltcaxe t’nac yehT .dab os eb ton thgim tI
,drocca nwo rieht fo dehctiwt srae reH
,raey siht gniraew saw naD elcnU trihs yzarc fo dnik tahw ksa ot tuoba saw ehS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
elbat eht fo ertnec yrev eht nI
esuoh eht fo ruoloc ehT
.reh fo daeha htap etercnoc eht morf esor taht taeh fo ezah eht ylraelc ees reh gnittel
,reffo ot dah sgninnuB taht tsepaehc eht
,reh dnuora deraor sadaciC
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.elims a htiw dehsinif yaK ”,paehc yllaeR“
.tsaef yaddim eht ot etubirt nwo rieht gnignirb hcae
.puorg llams eht ot adniL decudortni yaK
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.elggig reh edam llits ti tub
.sdub etsat reh revo decnad
.etircopyh uoy …uoy
,elims a decrof adniL
,dias ehs duol tuO
,nolemretaw decils fo yart A
,llac eht detanimod daD sa oediv eht fo emarf fo tuo devom ylwols dah elzzum esohw ,muM
fo dnuor gnisuor a detuohs dna ,devaw
,kcilliK yb ”maH“ saw sihT
.tnuocca knab reh morf emac rettam eht ni yas lanif eht tuB
,yad samtsirhC erofeb skeew owt tuobA
.tnemom a ekat ot doog tlef tI
”.gnizama ’nikcuf s’tI“
.sdrow reh pu gnitae
.notsecnuaL“ .looc oot yaw tub ,thgil saw taht eciov a ni sugnA deksa
,ot tnaw I .oN“ .deksa yaK
.ti dekcehc dna ,gnikniht tuohtiw ,enohp reh tuo dellup ehS .neve ,ypmuJ
.hcaer reh fo tuo eb syawla dluow deraef d’ehs gnihtemos
.ppa txet eht revo derevoh lian kcalb reh tub
.delims dna denrut tibbar eht kcirE ”.kcuF
.ecnart reh fo tuo adniL dellup eciov s’yaK ”?og ti d’woH“
sessalg reh morf dehsinav yllanif gof ehT
”?ti t’now ,daD ruoy htiw laed pleh ll’tahT“
.daD ,riaf s’tahT“
,uoy erad woH …I“ .denethgit
,doots adniL   .redro nA
stekcaj dna strihs tseb rieht gniraew enoyreve
”,em esucxe“ delbmum
,toh sa saw tI  kcilliK yb
.detrats adniL ”...mu ,s’tahT“ ”.mmM“
”?nhaagaywoh ,adniL ,yad’G“ .euqebrab deppot-talf ,dlo na dna sriahc fo elcric eht neewteb derednaw ylizal ohw
.swalc reh htiw repap eht yawa erot dna
.neercs eht morf taews fo reyal niht eht evomer ot strohs reh tsniaga ti gnipiw ylkciuq
.txen erew snwarp ehT
pu desnet spil reH
.noitasrevnoc eht morf yawa erot noitnetta reh dna
,yawa sertemolik derdnuh neetneves revo deldnahnam saw ecived ’stnerap reh sa
,esuoh erahs tneduts yttihs dna paehc demaercs
,troter ot htuom sih denepo daD
.meht llac dluohs uoy ebyam ,yenoH“
dellup yaK  .nael dna ydruts saw flesreh yaK fi neve
,ylneddus pu doots ehS
.reh htaeneb saw ti ekiL
.gab shtrowlooW s’adniL pu dleh dna
,taem eht fo tser eht nwod deflow ylideerg adniL
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
dalas otatop dna ,dalas atsap ,dalas neerg A
.guh a otni god eht gnillup neht dna nepo rood neercs eht gnihsup
.gnipoord morf liat reh pots ot gniyrt ,thguoht adniL ,ton m’I
?etteuqite txet dnatsrednu t’ndid ohw remoob a yb tnes egassem a gnizylana-revo yletelpmoc tsuj ehs saw rO
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ylwols deddon yaK ”.thgiR .hA“
.adniL ,uoy evol I“  .ebyaM
,ereht dnats tsuj ot reisae saw tI
.yppah eb ot evresed uoY“
,taen eht kcab dednah ehS ”.sruoy nepo woN“
,draCoG reh rof tekcop strohs reh ni gud ehS
.pleh dluow mah fo dnuor rehtona spahrep tub
”.kcab eht dnuor og s’tel
”!elbatrofmocnu yadiloh tcefrep ruoy gnikam s’taht yrros m’I dna ,eno doog a eb ot gniog si efil ym erus ekam ot snoisiced drah emos ekam ot dah ev’I
”.ydaer si hcnul litnu tiaw ylbaborp lliw su fo tsom hguohtlA .yvveb samtsirhC ykeehc a htiw gnorw gnihtoN“ .dennirg yaK
.taht wonk uoy epoh I ,evarb yrev si gniod er’uoy tahW“
,etihw neeb ecno dah
,dlog dna etihw ni depparw tfig a tuo gnillup dna gab eht otni gnihcaer
.skeehc reh ta gnillup nirg llams a tlef tub
,seert eht ni reh evobA
.yadot emit doog a gnivah yllanif m’I tuB“
”!samtsirhC yrreM !adniL ,hO“  .delaid dna
.eert ognam eht deltsur ezeerb A
”.nwo ruoy tub sgnileef s’enoyna gniredisnoc tuohtiw ereht pu devom uoY
?noitadilav rof hctarcs etarepsed A
,tekcop reh fo tuo enohp reh gud dna
.tsrif netae eb dluow hcihw fo redro gnidnecsa dna
.remmus eht gnirud ecalp delooc a morf edistuo gniklaw enoyna yllaretil fo noitidart nailartsuA taerg eht saw sa
.dednopser reven d’ehS
.gniht dab a ro gniht doog a saw taht fi erus t’nsaw ehS .naeco hserF
.snwarp esoht ,nam hO
?eya ,taeh ’nikcuf sihT
.selbuab derettaps rettilg htiw
,reh ekil sreleeh eulb erew llac oediv eht fo dne rehto eht no sgod owt ehT
.dezzub enohp reh emityreve etatiseh dna ecniw reh gnikam
.ylimaf reh fo kniht reh gnikam meht etipsed
.neercs eht ta ylhsipeehs dekool dna ,desuap
,loop elddap seiddik elbatalfni na dnuora elcric hguor a demrof
.guh a otni reh dellup yaK ”.pmacs elttil uoY“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,thgir er’uoY“ ”.reverof dnuora yats ot em tcepxe t’nac eH“
.rood a fo mals eht yb dewollof
.ti htiw ruovalf mah ,yttaf
”?yako gniod uoy erA
.ezalg kciht eht fo neehs kcalb tsomla eht ot taem knip yciuj eht morf denetsilg mah dekab eht
,poord srae reh tlef llits adniL tub
,elcric luferac a ni degnarra erew
”.elbanosaer gnieb s’muM“
.trevo erom dna reivaeh tog stnih eht neht tuB
.ecaps eht rof lufetarg saw adniL
.aremac eht hguorht demaeb muM
yad wen hcae neht dna ,rettoh yna teg ylbissop ton dluoc ti taht erows ehs yad hcaE
”.su htiw samtsirhC dneps dna nwod emoc dluohs uoY“
.ereh pu devil sdneirf reh fo tsom esuaceb saw ti yltsenoh tub
;yawyna derettam evah dluow ti taht toN
.rof gniksa m’I lla si ,daD ,ecneitaP
redluohs s’god eht no wap a decalp ehS .deciton yaK ,sihT
,tahc eht desolc adniL
.retteb leef thgim uoy meht ot klat uoy fI
”?gniod uoy woH“
”.noitisop a fo tib a ni muM ruoy dna em tfel s’ti tub ,sdneirf tisiv ot ereht pu er’uoy wonk I“ ”-t’ndluoc I tuB“
,troppus otni denrut dah tbuod taht emit nI
.puc citsalp raelc a otni emos flesreh deruop ehs nehT
,eert s’tnerap s’adniL fo pot eht gninroda eb dluow taht
sreh dellif adniL
,yrettub eht gniyrrac yletamitlu
.ylgniwonk ,yletavirp
.flah ni tiucsib a gnitib ,yaK dias ”,doog yllaer era esehT“
,dias dna dellac daD reh
.saw llits ehs pu dnuow woh detah ehS .ti nmaD
”.sgniht ot desu gnitteg llits m’I ,hO“
.yab ta taeh edistuo eht peek ot gnilggurts renoitidnoc ria
,elbat cincip citsalp eht ot noitargim eht dekram srelloh dna spoohW
.tey no evom ot ydaer etiuq ton tsuj s’daD ruoY
.ecaf reh ni gniwohs t’nsaw yteixna emas eht depoh ehS
.tnenamrep saw ti
”.tsrif og dluohs uoy kniht I“
,god eht dehtoos redluohs s’adniL no wap s’yaK fo hcuot ehT
,elzzum reh dekcil adniL ”?maH“
”.uoy ot taht od ll’ylimaF“
.yawa deppets ooragnak ehT
,tsap dezzihw seert krabrepap dna burcS
seenk reh no etalp repap eht decnalab ehS
”,samtsirhC yrreM ,uoy knahT“
.flesmih pleh t’ndluoc tsuj eh dediced daD nehw
”.muM ,samtsirhC yrreM“ ”.samtsirhC yrreM
?od ot em tnaw uoy od kcuf eht tahW
.klaw ot detrats dna ,ria dimuh
,yltnerappa ,dna doolf laciport lanoisacco eht diova ot stlits no tliub
flesreh rof degrof d’ehs taht egnahc eht fo lassimsid etelpmoc siH
.taht stnerap reh llet ot woh wonk t’ndid ehs dna ,reh gnitruh saw ti tuB .wonk did ehS
,ssarg eht no doof fo etalp eht gnicalp erofeb stna rof gnikcehC
.ti hguorht enihs nus eht gnittel dna xob eht fo tuo ti gnillup ,adniL dias
.guh a rof ni denael yaK ”.os epoh I .haeY“
,htym etelpmoc a saw erutaef rettal eht decnivnoc saw adniL
.deklat ehs sa esuoh eht hguorht adniL del yaK
.levon tsrif sih no gnikrow yltnerruc si dna
.mah samtsirhC s’yaK
”.taht od nac I ,muM eruS“
.redluohs reh thguac wap dennat ,gnorts A
enimsaj eht fo ylpeed dehtaerb adniL
”?morf uoy era erehw ,adniL ,oS“
,ooragnak eht dias ”,ycnaf ,hoO“
.oga syad eerht saw tahT
enabsirB ot notsecnuaL morf gnivoM
.deifi-lesnit ylivaeh saw lesnit troppus dluoc taht gnihtynA
.sdalas eht htiw yzarc tib a tnew kcirE dna eM
?esaelp ,niaga su llac uoy naC
-htiw ti netsirhc ot eniw yna evah t’nod ew emahs a s’tI“
,seuqebrab dekil adniL
.seye reh yb ylkciuq dewollof
,mah eht fo lufkrof gib a flesreh tuc dna
”.enim s’tahT“ .delkcuhc adniL
”?samtsirhC doog a gnivah uoy erA
.daD dna muM tuoba ykahs adnik llitS“
.samtsirhC rof pu dekcaj os syawla erew serafria ehT
oga shtnom xis dna
.redaelgnir sucric a fo ruovref eht htiw
,yletunim esor worb s’daD ”…I ,daD“
,tcaf a sa ti dias yaK
.don a reh evag god eht litnu adniL ffo seye reh ekat t’ndid ooragnak ehT
.erew samtsirhC rof snalp reh tahw deksa ylpmis yeht tsrif tA
”.ekil s’daD tahw wonk uoY“
”.daD ruoy htiw sdrow evah ot erus ekam ll’I
.tsiwt thgils a htiw denrettap dna ,peed
”,latsyrc s’ti ,dog ym hO“
?flesreh ti ksa ot gnikniht ton rof nialliv a ekil erom neve leef reh ekam ot tpecxe eveihca dluow ti kniht eh did tahW
,pu dekool sriahc deipucco eht ni slamina ehT
.tneserp depparw a dna
,setunim thgie tuoba ylno saw pots sub eht morf klaw ehT
.sknaht ni reh ta depeeb hcihw redaer cinortcele eht tsniaga ti deppat dna
.niaga reh tpurretni mih tel ot gniog saw ehs fi denmad saw adniL tub
enohp eht gnivohs dna yawa wap reh gnillup ,thguoht ehS !oN
.llac enohp eht fo knuf eht yawa ekahs ot hguone saw enola llems ehT
,duef driew siht otni ti gninrut er’uoy tuB
.ecuas yos htiw sgnilpmud krop deirf fo lluf lwob oobmab a ot txen thgir
.sredluohs eht yb god eht dleh dna kcab
.rebmeceD ni ton ,ainamsaT ot tekcit enalp a droffa dluoc ehs yaw on saw erehT
?yletarepsed os reh ot klat ot detnaw yeht fi ,reh llac yeht t’ndluoc lleh eht yhW
,retfos ekops dna
.reh ot txen nwod tas yaK  .ezalg ypoog
.doom eurt reh yawa nevig evah dluow ti sa llac oediv eht ni liat reh ees t’ndluoc yeht dalg saw ehS
,kcab namow gnuoy llat eht guh ot tseb reh did adniL
,zzub enohp reh tlef adniL
.doof trofmoc tcefrep eht llits saw ti tub
…t’nod I“  ”?ti did deneppah lufwa gnihton ,tsirhC“
”.esaelp won adniL ot klat ot ekil d’I taht kniht I ,ydnA“
,kcithcs yraropmet emos ekil ti gnitaerT
.yaK ,samtsirhC yrreM“
.won ytrap ruoy ot kcab teg uoy tel ll’I“ .dehgis ehS
,pot knat a gniraew deraeppa
.enasni gnikool tuohtiw dluoc ehs sa elzzum reh otni elims hcum sa tup ot deirt adniL