,raeh i sdrow eht gniretnuoc on si ereht ".won
,taefed ni noitulosba on si ereht
gninrael morf su pots tsap ecnelis fo sraey fi ees ot tsuj ,dedaertnu sliart s'tresed eht klaw ew
gnirit morf seye wolley ym peek ot wolga pmal a
ykseulB no scitna gnikaeuqs sti fo erom dnif nac uoY
.tsew eht ni thgifnug yna ot gnirb ot efink a
,ekirts ot fi sa tfola dleh reggad sih speek eh ,tsur fo sevac dna sliart niatnuom hguorht
.oot ,sdneirfyob dna sedalb fo swolb snetfos taht
.nworc sih morf gnillaf kcolmeh fo seniv htiw ezis llams
,llac ot emoc erutaerc-tirips yna dluohs
,emit siht tser ot epoh dna seye ym esolc i
,trofeuqoR .Q yggI yb
shturt fo erahs s'noil eht llet yeht ,sraet sih
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
fo wollef a sthgil
,yas i dna eelg sti htiw em stcefni nirg ysae sih
trofeuqoR .Q yggI yb meop a ,”nooM ehT
.ymene tsetaerg dna
.loow yvaeh hcum os ekil thgif gnol ruo morf nrohs snoitnetni tseb htiw nwod em tuc dna
.tegrof t'nod tub ,evigrof"
.niaga dlrow eht esruc dna ecalp rieht tegrof em ekil gniht sseltraeh dna kaew a dluohs ro
,swolb lanif dna seye ytpme fo maercs taht senots htiw tes dna enillatsyrc eno
,ecaf yldneirf a ees ot doog"
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,niaga ksa i ,eno gnuoy .swap débmun-egamad ym nopu doolb erom ron
.retfa em llik dna hcter em hctaw ot ,shtaerb neknurd htiw ,erows uoy
,trofeuqoR .Q yggI yb
.erahs i sdnuow eht" ,syas eh
.em htiw htap siht klaw dna" ,syas eh ",pu teg"
.tsehc sti ot esolc sdrac sti sdloh ohw
.htap tsekrad ym morf em tpek gniraor esohw uoy s'ti" ,yrc i ",stsaeb fo gnik dénam o"
.etis.wonkaeuqs@
llacer i sa taews em sekam selkcunk sih neewteb ,tuc ssecnirp ,seibur fo maelg eht
,ynapmoc tsetilop ni emoclewnu
,htgnertS ,naM degnaH“   yojne esaelP
”.thguos i gnol os eno eht eb tsum uoy taht hcus ecneitap dna elyts htiw ecnanetnuoc a
.efil ni etal gnihtrib htiw
.i ro uoy rof niaga raeppa ton lliw siht ekil ecnahc a dna
tresed yztilg eht morf retirw tar a
,tleb sih morf reggad a esaeler eh seod
.od i tahw fo hturt eht erab yal i dna ".peek i tser eht
.smaerd ym lla egavar dna peels ym tnuah ot
dneirf tseurt sa em tniap efil-ot-eurt detcelfer snis erehw sllah derorrim tub thguan ees i ,uoy tuohtiw
.won ,em nioj dna pu dnats
dna  ".ecrovid tfiws a naht layarteb erom on -- tfig a eb lliw thginot esimed ym tub
oot os ,sdne retniw tresed sa kciuq
,dneirf layor ym ,drows nedlog ruoy ehtaehsnu
.wolg gnivorppa s'noom eht ni slauqe era ew taht sraeppa neht ti ,dnats i sa dna
,egada dlo eht
emoc taht syoj eht lla gnitcepxe dna gnitnaw srehtom htiw sthgif eht dna sreificap deppid-eniw eht
,tnemlunna tnaw ton od i
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
.edlosi dna natsirt sa deniwtretni sa straeh ruo speek taht si ti tahw
”nooM ehT ,htgnertS ,naM degnaH“ saw sihT       ".tegrof
,floWcaM boR si sihT
eaf eht ro ,sehctiw ,snomed gnihceercs on
ekoms nosiop eht no sehctac htaerb ym dna
,relevart wollef ruoy
,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
noom eht stcelfer niks nworg-wen rednet sih
.NGISLLAC htiw