.gnos eht gnis lliw sevlow dna sgod ehT ;gnola meht sdib thgin ta yrc A
.thgila dlrow eht evoba sraoS thgin eht secreip hcihw ,yrovi ehT
gnoS lA yb meop a
wolg yklim sti fo ecnaillirb ehT
— flowcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
,sratiug tfos ekil gnignis rieht sekovE
,gnoS lA yb meop a uoy gnidaer si floWcaM boR yadoT dnA
;eciov ni denioj ,gnineve eht hguorhT
srats yb demarf ydob laitselec sihT
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY .9 raoR dna 8 gnaF ,ruoT dlroW
.tolgylop dna ,retirw yrruf
,gnoS lA yb ”ezinomraH“ saw sihT
;yks eht drawot slwoh delbmessA
,seigolohtna elpitlum ni dehsilbup neeb sah eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT ..rekih-
.lworp eht no ro tser ta rehtehW lwoh ot nraey yeht straeh mraw rieht nI
hctih flowerew
,”ezinomraH“   :yojne esaelP
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.yhw gniwonk tuohtiw detcennoC
.eciojer lla yeht noom eht drawoT
.serac rieht tsac yeht noom eht drawoT
,naicisum a si ohw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
- dliuG eht morf selaT gnidulcni
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT ta rotide na sa stsissa osla ooragnak der ehT
.wohs a htaeneb htrae eht sdneL
;serats dna pu skool woleb efil ehT