”.ecnis reve elpmaxe reh ot pu evil ot gniyrt neeb ev’I“
”,ydaerla ydal ym nelots sah xof yls a ees I“
”,uoy tuohtiw daeh ym revo retaw neeb evah dluow llits tI“
tuo dehcaer sogrA
,gniw eht ot derutseg ehS
”,teg nac I tahw ekat ll’I“
.sogrA ,ti timda I
.tfel doof fo ytnelp evah llits eW
,deedni degnahc evah semiT“
,sevil rieht fo tser eht otni no dna
.deR ,ereht thgir eb ll’I“
.deksa eh ”?ylimaf eht s’woH
swap sih revo liat sih htiw
.thgin eht ni tuoba evom ot deen rehtie dluohs ecnadiug emos sa evres dluow ti taht os ,tuo ton tub wol denrut saw pmal ehT
”.ti deen uoy kniht I
”.niaga ylraluger sremotsuc ym lla gniees ot drawrof gnikool m’I
yeht sA .doof eht fo krow kciuq edam yeht os
,ssih dna elzzis ot nageb retaw eht litnu
”,em morf nelots evah dluoc reve enoyna gniht eno ylno saw erehT“
.reh ssim llits I
ssergorp ni krow eht tuo ekam tsuj dluoc eH
elohtop ro kcarc lanoisacco eht diova ot mih dewolla dna esruoc no mih tpek noisiv thgin sih tub
.eurt sgnir yas uoy gnihtyreve tub
.deppots yeht erofeb
,tca lanif eht rof staes rieht ot denruter yehT
,siht fo tcepser nI
”.ot ekil d’uoy fi ,eruS“
.denioj ydaerla erew taht owt eht fo pot no wap rehto sih tup cenneF
.tfol gnipeels eht ot tnew taht sriats worran eht tsap
,steerts eht denil taht selpam dna smle eht fo swodahs eht otni dna ,sdnuorg lavitsef eht fo sdnuos eht morf yawa werd yeht sA
.dedne saw ti erofeb peels ot ffo detfird evah thgim ecneidua eht fo ynam
,hgih si noom eht
,nageb eh ”...reven uoY“
”?tuo dnif I dluow woh os peelsa syawla saw I“ .derewsna cenneF ”,taht wonk t’nod I ,lleW“ .dias eh
,taes elsia eht dah sogrA
enod saw siht elihw drow a ekops meht fo rehtieN
.rehctip retaw dna nisab htiw
.revaeW sogrA fo taht si
,denioj llits swaP
”?sogrA“ .derrits cenneF
.wodniw gnicaf-tsew eht deretne thgilnoom nwad-erp eht nehw denekawa sogrA
.erom ecno mih dnuora mra na tup ot sogrA wolla ot dneirf sih ot hguone esolc deklaw cenneF
”.hguone uoy fo rehtie knaht reven nac I dna
tnemniatretne tsenif eht gnignirb ni deyalp evah uoy trap eht rof
denepo srood eht tnemom siht ta ,yletanutroF
roolf niam eht no tsrif
reh dnuora mra na tup lemmaH dna denway ardnoS
,dedda eh sa sogrA drawot denrut dna
.erom yna syas ro skniht enoyna tahw erac t’nod I taht hguone dlo gnitteg tsuj m’I .revef oN“
tnemegaruocne tneuqerf dna ,ecivda
.llet ot yrots eht sah sogrA
.srosnops rof detangised aera eht ni
,knird dna doof fo syart htiw nedal denruter lemmaH dna yzuS
.setunim net tuoba rof sroodtuo teg did yeht ,noissimretni dnoces eht tA .dias eh
siht htiw ecnad a fo ronoh eht evah I dluoC“
,daeh sih gnikahS
.emit eht ssap ot gnittahc
,deddon dna dennirg tacbob ehT
.ezeeuqs elttil a dneirf sih evag eh sa
tsetorp ot deirt yzuS
”.revo evoM .mraw meht teg ot em no swap dloc esoht gnittup ton er’uoY .hnu-
.mih esufer dluoc eno on thguoht sogrA taht
”?he ,gninrom emoc skool dlrow eht woh ees dna
.gnineve gniwollof eht no yalpsid skrowerif a htiw dne dluow lavitsef eht nehw
selbat ecivres eht ot yzuS htiw gniog no detsisni lemmaH
.deksa ehs ”?meht rof tuo gnikrow taht si woh dnA“
.wap eno yb rood eht drawot dneirf sih dellup sogrA
”,siht rof uoy teg ot gniog m’I“
.delims dna ruf etihw nwo sih tsniaga swap kcalb llams esoht fo tsartnoc eht denigami eH
”...esuoh eht otni kcab deb rehtona teg dna dnuora sgniht evom I litnu tub
orevO ovitlA yb ”emoH tsevraH“
sdrow eht dehtuom dna seye sih deworran sogrA
.nehctik eht otni kcab emac cenneF
,srosnops ro stnapicitrap wen yna fo serutangis eht htiw detadpu eb syawla tsum dna ,esac ssalg a ni ,oot ybbol eht ni deyalpsid eb
.deR ,uoy dessim I dnA“ .delims sogrA
.ssorc eb ot gnidneterp ,dias ehs ”,maH ,taht potS“
”.eunitnoc gnineve eht tel ,uoy yarp I woN
dednuos lleb etunim eerht ehT
pot eht ta etalp ssarb devargne na htiw euqalp nedoow egral a gnidloh
rood eht tuo tnew yehT
tsiaw s’dneirf sih dnuora mra sih tup eH
”.uoy revo lwarc ot em tnaw uoy sselnu tsrif pu teg ot evah uoY“
roolf doow dlo eht no slianeot fo kcilc tniaf eht dna sdaptooF
.topaet anihc eht otni
,ecnelis rof fi sa swap nepo sih pu dleh
,ylluftsiw dehctaw sogrA
spsalcwap dna sguH
.orevO ovitlA rednu nozamA no dna
.depacse uoy dalg era nwot eht fo tser eht dna ew esruoc fo
.sutats ruoy fo sklof htiw gnizilaicos ,siht od dluohs I erus ton m’I“ .dettimda yzuS
”.stik eerht gnivah dna deirram gnieb retfa neve ,hcum degnahc t’nsah ylniatrec ehS“
,srosnops ,srebmem draob
.knird hcum oot tib a ylbaborp dna thgin gnol a dah ev’eW
.lla dna secitnerppa gnihcaet
.don a htiw dias sogrA
.pleh ot regae syawla dna tluaf a ot suoreneg
.esiwrehto ereh eb t’ndluow I
.thgilnus gninrom eht otni dna
,mih revo mra s’flow eht dellup dna wodniw eht ecaf ot revo dellor cenneF ”.dooG“
,oiduts dna nehctik eht morf llah eht nwod cenneF dediug dna
ruf s’enoyreve ni teg dna llah nwot eht tuoba gnah t’nac I
.drawretfa knird a ro doof revo ti gnissucsid deyojne dna
.noom eht rednu rehtegot doots yeht sa
,sogrA ot eniw fo ssalg a gnidnaH
.ydaerla retteb leef I“
.trofmoc ruoy rof edistuo og ro tuoba evom ot eerf leeF“
”?emoh uoy klaw I llahS“ .os did flow ehT
.rehtegot sehsid eht kcats ot nageb dna
,enut ztlaw dlo na otni detrats artsehcro ehT
,puorg eht dnuor tnew
”.no og sgniht tub ,egnahc semiT
.esualppa citsaisuhtne htiw dellif saw muirotidua eht ,pu kcab emac sthgil eht dna
,nemeltneg ,seidaL“
sesnel zen-ecnip demmir-revlis sih ffo detnilg thgil mid ehT
,sehsid reppus gnilooc eht htiw tfel saw sogrA
”.ereh uoy evah ot dalg er’ew dna stseug deronoh lla er’uoY
”.leurc dna diputs os leef I dnA“
”.yap ot tner on dna ,nwo ruoy lla ,won evah uoy naht uoy rof ecaps regral a ekam dluow yrarbil ehT
,enog ylraen saw thgil ehT
,sretcarahc fo tsac egral a ecudortni taht senecs lareves sah tca tsrif ehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.moor eht deyevrus eh sa
”...suoreneg dna teews fo gnikaepS“ .dennirg cenneF
,denilced evah thgim sogrA
.yrlever dna gnicnad timrep ot
.stca eerht ni yalp esrev a si thgiN nmutuA na fo maerD .hcuot taht fo
.mra sih revo nikpan a gniksihw dna gnidnats
.tnessa sih deddon flow eht dna
,elttek egral sih llif ot retaw gnipmup saw sogrA dna demirp saw pmup nehctik eht emit eht yB
hguohT .sogrA ,sboj ruo gniod tsuJ“
”,thgir llA“ .delims sogrA
”,hguone efas er’eW
.aet gnipeets eht emit ot
.ecin eb dluow reppus fo dnik emos tub ,gnihtyna ro ,thgin lla ecnad ot deraperp m’I taht toN
.roiretni tilnoom eht otni noinapmoc sih ediug ot mra sih gnidnetxe
.flesmih koohs dna pu doots sogrA
,esuoh siht gnignirb dna
noitacifisrev revelc rof ton ti ereW
.yawa deid spuccih s’cenneF dna
,snoitubirtnoc laicnanif esohw rosnops a
”?ecnad siht fo ronoh eht em od uoy dluow
”.syawla sa suoreneg dna teewS“
.tnemom a rof ecnelis ni esolc rehto hcae dleh sdneirf owt ehT
.roolf ecnad eht gnieye saw lemmaH
.demialcxe eh ”,su no ycrem evah sinaC“
.rood kcab eht dna nehctik eht drawot dedaeh eh os
ksud eht ni rehto hcae ot derettan sdriB
,ni flesmih tel dna rood dekcolnu eht denepo tub ,rewsna na rof tiaw ton did eH
”.wonk uoy ,nerraW ehT ta uoy tuohtiw emas eht t’nsi tsuj emit aeT“
.daeh sih koohs eH
.wap eht no cenneF dettap dna
ereh tseR“ .elffins ot deunitnoc
htolc eht fo llef eht no gnitser elttuhs eht dna
.oiduts eht fo edis raf eht no
”.ssergorp emos edam ew kniht I dna
.rosseforp fo dnik yna eb ot tuo tuc m’I erus ton m’I“
”.gninrom eht ni yrros eb ylerus d’ew dna taht yfitsuj ot hguone dloc s’ti kniht t’nod I tub ,ereh roolf eht no peels dluoc ew ,lleW“
dekniw lemmaH ”?dratsum oN“
,elgnij a htiw puc hcae ediseb dednal
.rebmemer nac I sa gnol sa rof uoy devol ev’I
gnihtaerb ydaets s’dneirf sih tub gnihton raeh dluoc eH
rettahc otni detpure seciov derdnuh owt tsomlA
pal sih ta nwod dekool xof ehT
”.yaw taht ni gnimoc meht ees dluow eno on esuaceB“
.ardnoS efiw sih dna mih nioj ot deirruh yehT
.esoppus I ,thgir er’uoY“
.yawa elim a tuoba ,esuoh arepo wen eht drawot nwotnwod denrut dna
”,erom uoy gniees ot drawrof gnikool er’ew dnA“
.esuoh eht fo kcab eht morf emac
.htaerb eno derahs yeht dna
.deralced ehs ”,gnol erofeb aet tuo gniruop dna sehsid gnihsaw meht evah ll’uoy tbuod t’nod I“
pihsnoitaler rieht fo htped eht gnittimda yllanif tub
,thguoht sogrA ,tey mih brutsid ot deen oN
.meht ot denokceb dna wap a desiar
resopmoc emas eht yb dnoces a otni ztlaw eht degdirb artsehcro elttil ehT
.raey eht fo nortap ruo sa
”.lli saw I sselnu emityad eht ni peels dluoc reveN
,etal si ruoh eht ,esac yna nI“ .detsisni sogrA
esor flow eht taht htiw dna
.mih ot ti dednah dna puc s’cenneF ot
”?swodahs eht ni gnidiH
.elavtseW fo nwot nrehtuos eht ni
,ti gnidloh neeb dah eh fi sa
.elavtseW fo spotfoor dna seert detteuohlis eht dniheb rebme gniyd a ekil dewolg nus ehT
”.pu gninaelc ni trap ym od I taht riaf ylno si ti ,tsaef eht thguorb lemmaH dna uoY“
srecnad eht htiw gnola dedualppa sogrA
.esnes edam ti ,esuoh laiciffo eht ni gnivil dna royam erew uoy nehW
,erac ym ot revo oiduts siht denrut dna deriter ehs ecnis sraey neetfiF
rehtegot tif llits yeht
”.uoy htiw ti evah llits dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.sogrA ,uoy evol od yllaer yehT“
,neeb evah dluoc reve I sa tnatropmi sa tib yreve erew lemmaH dna uoY
”.ecin sleef ti ereh ni pu gnimraw si evots eht
.ynoclab eht fo egde eht ta gniliar eht ot drawrof deppets eh os
.detsetorp flow eht ”,t’nseod ti tuB“
tib a dednuos ti tub ,dehgual xof ehT
flow eht dnuora mra na tup cenneF
esolc mih dleh sogrA
,t’now I“ .ylthgit no dleh dna delffins cenneF
.tixe eht ot ti edam dah meht fo enon dna
,esuoH dliuG nottahC eht ni revaewretsaM a dna
.sesion gnilworg tfos gnikam
.tsal ta emoh er’uoY
,snekcihc htiw nurrevo eb d’ew
.kcurts kcolc eht semit eht detnuoc ro
.egats eht ot gniwob dna
niatruc eht fo tnorf ni tuo emac
eotpit no doots ehS
.tuo eseht detniop flow eht nehw
.hcum oot dias dah eh fi rednow ot nageb sogrA
.ti ot gnitniop dna
tem seson rieht os ti desiar dna
",ovitlA" sa onimA yrruF dna ,lysaeW
ti decaf cenneF nehw rood ’sogrA fo
.taht gnitcepxe t’nsaw I“ .deddon sogrA
.deR ,era uoy erehT“
.deistruc tibbar eht
?yalp eht retfa ereht nwod llorts a rof pu ew erA“
royam saw cenneF elihw
meht evoba swodniw eht ni gnimoc thgilnoom ehT
.tser eht morf noitcerid etisoppo eht gniog cenneF dna sogrA htiw ,ynapmoc detrap yeht dna
.kcirt s’rorujnoc a gniod fi sa ,nikpan sih rednu morf top dratsum a decudorp dna
,seog gniyas ralupop eht sA
,rehto eht no moordeb eht dna ,edis eno no saw rood yrarbil ehT
.slrans dna selgnat emos sah ti ,wen gnihtyna ekil ,lleW“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,orevO ovitlA yb
”.noitidart wen a gninnigeb era ew
,puorg ertaeht eht fo rosnops raluger a saw sogrA ecnis dnuora lla selkcuhc werd meht neewteb ekoj gnidnats gnol sihT
.eerht rehto eht ta dnuora dekool dna dleif tekram eht drawot daeh sih dekcoc lemmaH
.wob a htiw dias eh
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”,yllaiciffo ,taht si ti hO“
,sbir sih rednu morf mra s’xof eht eerf ot tib a gnitfihS
llaw nedrag eht no nus gnisir eht fo thgil knip detcelfer esuffid eht dna
,elbat eht ot denruter srecnad ruof ehT
.mih esaeler dna dnif ot dekrow
.keehc eht no flow etihw eht ssik ot pu dehcaer dna
,raed ym ,yzuS“ .delkcuhc eh
nwot siht ni sgniht erom tol a no eb dluohs eman ruoY“
enog saw noom eht litnu
”?rehtona eno fo derit eb d’ew tcepxe uoy t’ndluow sraey eseht lla retfA .uoy dessim I
.yletaidemmi derewsna cenneF tub
teerts eht nwod deklaw yeht
.pu gnimoc si nus eht ees I“
.sraey eseht lla yldab os uoy gnitaert rof yrros m’I“
,taht fo etips nI
,tuo emac srotca rehto owt dna
”,esruoc fo ,uoy dlot evah dluow I“
boh eht no ti decalp eh
ecnetsixe otni gnidliub siht gnirb depleh
.elbat eht no wap reh htiw emit tpek ehs sa erauqs ecnad eht gnihctaw saw ohw
,yllanoisacco swap rieht rednu deltsur sevael nellaF
”.thginot su htiw ereh si eh eveileb I
.elkcuhc a htiw deksa eh
.dehcatta etalp ssarb llams nwo sti dah ecaps tsrif ehT
,ti rof nosaer a dah uoy thguoht uoY
.raebsekahS evol I hcum woh wonk uoY“
”,hsiw uoy sa enod si ti erus ekam ll’eW
,revaeW sogrA ronoh ot
.nwo sih neewteb wap ’sogrA ekat ot tuo gnihcaer
.noitanitsed sih deraen eh sa
.dleh erew stekram ylhtnom eht erehw dleif eht ot nwot hguorht deklaw yeht sa reraelc werg dna
.emit a rof tnelis deniamer cenneF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dootsrednu syawla ev’I ,dnatsrednu I“
,mih fo tnorf ni tuo sgel sih gnihctertS
.erofeb sraey ynam mih nevig dah cenneF eno eht
,deronoh eb dluohs ohw I ton si tI
.yas uoy sa ,eurt ooT“
”.taht raeh ot deveiler era uoy kniht thgim ew“
.nwod tas ehs sa tibbar eht ot denrut sogrA
.enod eb ot tnegru gnihtoN
.elims elttil a htiw deksa eh
noom lluf eht fo ecnaillirb eht rednu wed htiw derettilg
”,ddo elttil a sleef
,deunitnoc esualppa eht hcihw gnirud ,esuap a retfA
.uaerub dna deb retsop ruof yvaeh sti htiw
.aedi doog a ekil sdnuoS“
”,pu gnidliub eht tup ot dekrow ohw enoyreve dda s’teL“ .dehgual sogrA
.od ot enorp saw ti sa ,tuo tnew dna derettups pmal eht yllautnevE
.no dessap ehs ecnis evlewt dna
.esor ti sa niaga moor eht nethgirb noos dluow noom lluf eht hguoht
secnamrofrep s’nosaes siht fo lla etacided ot
.eettimmoC tekraM eht fo riahc saw sogrA dna
.sogrA ,skeew rof uoy fo hcum nees t’nevah ew oS“
.ylmrif ti desolc dneirf sih sa
.nepo ton erew muirotidua eht ot srood eht taht hguone ylrae llits dna
.laets ot esuoh eht ni elttil s’ereht dnA
rehto hcae ta gnilims tas yehT
.dehgual srehto eht dna
.eye wolley eno dekniw xof ehT
”.ees nac uoy sa efarac eht ni eniw ,draknat
elzzum nwo sih no sriah yarg wef a naht erom htiw tacbob A
”,aet emos ekam I elihw etunim a rof
tI“”.sraey eseht lla dneirf raed a hcus neeb evah uoY
.nwod ecaf sih debbur dna
devloser erew snoisufnoc eht lla hcihw ni
”,derons reven uoY“ .dehgual sogrA
,skoob dehsilbupnu tey sa eht ni raeppa serutnevda rieht fo emoS
doow dna rednit eht ot hctam a tes eh retfa ylnO
srotcerid fo draob eht fo noitnetni eht ecnuonna ot gnineve siht ronoh ym si ti
.elggig ardnoS edam hcihw ,seye sih derevoc dna taht ta decniw sogrA
.kcits sih fo daeh yvaeh eht htiw
.redluohs eht no xof eht gnittap ,dias flow eht
rood eht ta kcab dekool cenneF
,tnemesuma lacirtaeht eht dedne esualppa dna rethgual ytraeH
.ardnoS ot txen flesmih detaes tacbob eht sa
”emoH tsevraH“ saw sihT   ----   .rehtegot
.swap erab ot dloc deniamer roolf enots eht hguoht
.oiduts eht fo rood eht ta doots yeht litnu ecnelis ni niaga deklaw meht fo owt ehT
”.yb dna yb og tsum ew peels ot
”.sraey eseht lla denrae ev’uoy esiarp eht morf knirhs t’noD .ti wonk uoY
.eugnot sih dekcilc sogrA
”?revef a evah uoy oD
cenneF dna lemmaH elihw egatsoh mih dleh dna  sogrA deppandik
.oiduts s’dneirf sih drawot
”?uoy t’nerew ,oot siht no ni erew uoy esoppus I“ dias dna
”,liob ot setunim wef a tsuj ekat lliw tahT“
.elbat eht no spuc rieht tfel dna
,esuoh arepo eht ta devirra yeht
.niaga kaeps dluoc egats eht no nooccar eht taht os hguone yawa delkcirt esion ehT
spotfoor eht evoba gnibmilc ylwols saw noom lluf eht tub
.evah I dneirf suoreneg tsom ,tseraed
,emit a ta stneduts evif ro ruof ylno ,llams erew spuorg eht tuB
.yad eht fo trap tsael ta rof krow ot kcab og nac I nehT
”.taht rof yenom ruoy ekat t’ndluow I“
,tcejbus eht degnahc sogrA
”.pordkcab eht tsuj saw I
”.gnorts llits dna mraw si ,esimorp I
.staes rieht dnif ot pu denil dworc lufreehc eht dna
.draobpuc a morf rehctip klim a dna ,raj yenoh a
.niaga seye sih desolc eH
.gnicnad ni detseretni hcum neeb reven dah eh hguoht
.steknalb eht rednu mih dnuora erew smra s’xof eht dna
seitilibisnopser ssenisub dna civic ni degagne llits
.xof eht ediseb niaga nwod tas eh dna
,giwT reviR eht drawot redluohs sih revo derutseg eH
si yrots s’yadot dna
.nwot ruo ot tnemhcirne larutluc dna
?uoy lliw ,srevotfel eseht tuoba su llet woN“
,evitca dna elppus mih tpek krow sih dna
teertS niaM nwod deklaw cenneF sa yks eht fo strap rekrad eht ni sevlesmeht delievnu ,tsethgirb dna tsedlob ,srats tsrif ehT
.ni demihc cenneF
”?su rof deucser lemmaH dna uoy evah seicaciled tahW
ssalgruoh ynit a fo epahs eht ni remit gge na revo denrut sogrA
”.krad dna dloc eht ni tuo og ot deen oN“
”?eb ton I dluoc woH“
?uoy od ,taht kcol t’nod llits uoY“
,ti denepo dna hctal eht denrut sogrA
wap reh ni drac egral a gnivaw yb ecnelis rof derutseg neht wob a rof
,ardnoS ot denrut eH
eht otni denael cenneF ”.uoy ees ot reippah neve m’I“ .tnialpmoc eht gnirongi ,dias eh ”,emoh eb ot dalg m’I“ .ecarbme mraw a otni dna
,erus m’I ,devresed lleW .thginot ertaeht eht ta esirprus elttil a tog uoy raeh I“ dias tibbar eht
.mih ta delims ardnoS dna
.snoitcennoc fo kcal ,sesac emos ni
.tnesba saw flow ruo elihw flesym htiw od ot tahw rof ssol a ta yldediced neeb ev’I“
tilnu saw pohskrow niam ehT
.drawno mih degru dna
.meht daer ot stnaw enoyna
”.lla ta rettam t’nseod ti gnidneterp era uoy ereh dnA
.roolf tfihsekam eht ssorca yawa reh delriws yltfed eh dna
,retiaw yffuts a fo ria eht htiw ,detpurretni lemmaH
”.gnorw saw I ,thgir erew uoY
erus ton m’I sriomem ym gnitirw tuoba thguoht ev’I hguoht dna ,ereht
.swap sih gnibburcs sa llew sa
.nerrab morf raf erew seert eht dna gnuoy saw nmutua eht tub
.yltfos delworg xof eht ,detarapes yeht sA
,seman ruoy lla raeb dluohs euqalp tahT
,elzzum dna srae sih revo wap a nur ot emit dah xof ehT
”.sdnats gnidliub eht sa gnol sa ees ot lla rof
,nemeltneg dna seidaL“
.don a htiw dias lemmaH
.rettil emas eht morf sbuc owt ekil
”.won yad eht fo tsom em deen yeht erehw ega taht ta era nerdlihc ehT
.saw ti woh tsuj s’tahT
,ylevitnetta delttes ecneidua eht nehW
”,sseug I ,nrut ym ,KO“
erar oot saw noisacco eht tuB
.seip nekcihc dna sehciwdnas tuoba noissucsid feirb emos dewollof erehT
,elbaliava saw ti nehw klim htiw aet nwo sih koot flow ehT
,dlohserht eht revo ecnO
.derewsna eh ”,wonk I“
elbat tnacav ybraen a morf riahc a koot cenneF
.ecaps eht tuohguorht draeh ylisae saw taht
cenneF leef ot desirprus saw eh
,meht deen uoy dluohS“
,emit fo daeha uoy dlot ew fi sedalocca yna tpecca reven d’uoy wenk eW
mih rof depmup sogrA dna ,dias cenneF
,noitcudorp a dessim ylerar yehT
.neht emoh og uoy ekam t’now I“
.taht ot gnihton dias dna dekculc tsuj sogrA
,hguoht ,flesmih peels dluoc eh erofeB
.tsal ta seye nwo sih desolc eh dna
.ereht revo uaerub eht no hsurb a s’erehT“
a sa degnarra lla saw ti os
.nrecnoc kcom ni srae s’xof eht neewteb wap a dial eH
,erahs ot yppah eb ll’I dna ,moor s’erehT
ecaps tnacav a dnuof puorg eht erofeb sgniteerg tuo dellac dna
”.metsys ecitnerppa eht fo ecalp ni
.stnemurtsni dna cisum rieht yawa tup ot nageb dna
derewsna eh ”,yllautca ,ma I“
.ssenkrad eht ni neesnu ,delims flow ehT
eniw dna doof eht rof yap ot deirt sogrA nehw tub ,taht ot deerga ehs dna
.edis rehto s’flow eht no ecalp nwo sih ot gninruter erofeb sogrA ot txen yzuS gnitaes fo erutseg tnallag a gnikam ,revo ti dellup dna
nihc s’xof eht rednu wap sih tup eH
lemmaH drawot denrut eh nehT .ardnoS ta neht
”.oot ,reh dewo I tnuoma gniniamer eht evagrof ehs lliw reh ni dnA
,niaga gniliar eht ta pu doots yllanif sogrA
”,on ,eno tnorf eht toN“
.dehgual dna mih ot daeh reh dewob eod ehT
taht elots uoy dnA“
.yenom sih desufer eod eht
.rae sih ni derepsihw dna
”...eerht ,owt ,enO .thgir llA
”,deR ,gninroM“ .oot denway sogrA
dnats hsaw denoihsaf dlo dna
,dneirf tsednik eht dna
.kniht I gnineve eht rof nwod dewols evah sgniht tub
.nirg a htiw dias ehs
sogrA dnuora smra htob tup xof ehT
.dellac xof eht ”!yetihW“
deralced dna woble s’lemmaH koot ardnoS
.dedaerht dna depraw gnieb saw mool eht nehw yaw eht fo tuo eb dluow ti erehw detacol
.won sraey evif rof
”.hguoht doog yrev si sihT“
.drawretfa lewot eht mih dednah dna ,debburcs eh elihw
hguone lufepoh dekool seye dlog s’xof ehT
”.hcum taht htrow t’nera nray dna skooB
.sraey ekil demees ti tub ,htnom a ylno saw ti wonk I“
”?taht evigrof yllaer uoy naC
.kcolc oiduts eht fo kcit suoronos eht dna
meht fo ruof eht dezingocer ohw stnediser nwot ynam yb deipucco
.erom ro raey txen eht revo stneduts fo puorg emas taht gnihcaet eb lliw sretsam rehto lareveS
”,evah uoy deedni sA“
.tpels yeht dna ,desimorp eh
”?uoy evah ,erutluc elttil a teg ot emoc ev’uoy oS“
?uoy gnirb I nac tahW
,depsag eh ”,dloc si roolf ehT
”?deneppah sah taht gnihtyreve retfa nevE
thgim sgniht hcus woh tuoba deirrow ohw eno eht neeb syawla dah xof ehT
repat warts a esu eh did hctac ot nageb ti dna
,yrots siht ni sretcarahc niam ehT
.steknalb nevowdnah eht rednu delgguns erew htob emit trohs nI
,retroppus eno ot
enola hcuot yb flesmih gnimoorg
,llew reh wenk reven I
.eno elgnis yreve
tcaf ni dah spuorg tsimertxE
,demialcxe yzuS ”,cenneF .rM yhW“
.derepsihw eh ”,yrc t’now I
.seert eht fo edahs eht ni neve raeppa ot nageb sthgilhgih rethgirb dna
dewob snaicisum eht sa
ti was eno on hguoht
”.dne eht ta stset rieht dessap stneduts ym lla dna revoc ot desoppus erew ew spets eht hguorht meht tog I tuB
.ssenhsiloof fo sraey eseht lla retfa em evah ll’uoy fi ,si tahT
wap ’sogrA fo og tel cenneF
.pmup llams eht ta derutseg dna
saw ohw dneirf sih ot gnitniop
.taht ta delkcuhc ardnoS
.loof dekcen-ffits a neeb ev’I
.elbat nedoow eht no pmal lio eht ot emalf a refsnart ot
”.raed ,sogrA ,ti esufer ot uoy rof etal ooT“
,krad yrev werg moor ehT
”?aet erom ekam I llahS“ .pu tas eH
.wap sih ekat dna revo hcaer
lliw tI .eman rieht ot txen noitisop rieht tup nac I os ti ngis ot rebmem draob dna ,rosnops ,rebmem tsac yreve ksa dna
”.elbbin ot tib a ro eniw emos dnif dluoc ew erus m’I dna enif si rehtaew ehT
”,tsafkaerb emos rof nerraW ehT ot nwod pop tsuj thgim ew gnikniht saw I yllautcA“
dneirf dlo sih ediseb hcneb eht no tas flow ehT
,tib a tsuj ,yenoh dedda eH
.deksa sa hctal eht denrut tub ,mih dlot cenneF
.loohcs ni nerdlihc llits htob erew yeht nehw neeb dah ti ,mih ot demees ti ,ylekil tsoM
.deR ,sraet erom oN“ .dias eh
,erutseg detcepxenu siht yb desirpruS
.su nioj nac uoy dalg os m’I“
xof etirovaf ym nehw
.tnew yeht ffo dna
.dennirg dna xof eht ta dekool eH
.dehgual flow ehT
,werc dna tsac gnizama ruo fo srebmem ,lla evoba dna
.noos emit yna toN“
.dneirf sih drawot gninael
”,tegrof reven ll’I“ .deksa eh
,evocla na ni ksed llams a ot tnew cenneF  ”.etunim eno tsuJ
.sogrA .rM ,remmus siht netae ev’uoy eip brabuhr hcum woh em dlot einnA“
,selkcip emos ,rettub dna daerb eyr ,ereh seip nekcihC“
,rohtua eht yb noitnevni retcarahc evitanigami dna
wap dereffo s’cenneF detpecca ehS
.reh tpurretni sogrA evah ot ylno
,deen naht tibah fo tuo erom kcits gniklaw a deirrac xof dlo ehT
.deR ,won uoy tog ev’I“
.llah ecnartne eht ni ereht ecarbme rehtona otni xof eht dellup sogrA
ot gnihton si erehT .revol ,peels dna won hsuH“
,nageb ehs ”,su nioj uoy evah ot ecin woH“
cenneF .hcneb denoihsuc a otno nwod dneirf sih desae eh erehw
.spoteert eht evoba llew nesir won
,ytiniffA ruF no dnuof eb nac tra dna seirots esohw stnelat ynam fo esroh ecnassianeR a
sraey ynam rof ecrof ecilop elavtseW eht fo rotcepsni feihc ,lemmaH saw tI
”.oga gnol flesym ot hturt eht dettimda evah dluohs I
,ertaeht enif siht fo snortap
”.ti no detsisni syawla rezaM
.delkcuhc flow ehT
.niaga nway dna hcterts ot nageb cenneF erofeb ,hguoht ,owt ro etunim a ylno saw tI
.hcum taht em dessim t’nevah uoy wonk I
”.gnol os rof uoy nwonk evah yllaer I fi sa sleef ti ,thgir er’uoy tuB
ssalg ynit eht ni
sdnuos fo tsetfos eht ylno edam swap erab siH
doow derracs eht no wodahs a tsac noom gnisir eht fo thgil tsrif ehT
.ekawa saw eh taht won ,pu neeb evah dluow sogrA yllamroN
,dworc eht dennacs ehS
.elbigirrocni er’uoY“
.krow sih ediug ot noom lluf eht fo thgil eht gnisu
?ereh selbat no gnitiaw t’nera uoy ylerus tuB“ .dedda cenneF
.ni kcab emac flow eht sa tsuj rood taht tuo gnimoc saw cenneF
.dias flow eht ”,esaelp ,rood taht no hctal eht nrut tsuJ“
”?gnihtyreve dna llaw enots eht gnibmilc rehtob yeht dluow yhw os ,tnorf eht ni klaw ylisae dluoc enoemoS .sseug I tibah tsuJ
elavtseW fo sogrA
.lemmaH htiw ffo deklaw ehs sa daeh sih koohs flow ehT
wap eno ni pmal lio eht pu dekcip sogrA
,htoob doof eht ta tuo gnipleh neeb ev’I“ .derewsna yzuS
tcetihcra eht morF“ .dias eh
.cenneF ta drah dereep dna skcart sih ni deppots flow ehT
delkcirt dnas ehT
”,srood dekcol reven uoy thguoht I“
esuoh arepo eht etisoppo dnal krap ehT
.nedrag eht ni teliot tip eht esu ot derreferp sogrA taht dna
.tnemssarrabme ro raef tuohtiw
taht won dna hguoht yllihc si gnineve ehT
uoy fo eno yreve dna hcae tub
hcaorppa moorssalc a tuo gniyrt er’yehT
,nwo sih desiar dna
.pu mih deppirt evah esiwrehto thgim taht
.erom hcum dna ti fo tib yreve evresed uoY“ .deksa eh
”.htiw aet rof og ot enoyna evah t’ndid tsuj I“ .decrof
.taht fo enoN“
.deb eht fo egde eht drawot xof eht dehsup eH
.oot uoy evol I“ delworg xof eht
”?uoy evah ,tsal ta ti fo retteb thguohT“
,eye reh ni elkniwt neddus a htiW
.mih depacse enihw tniaf a ,ti niartser ot troffe tseb sih fo etips ni dna ,guh
nwod tis ot srehto eht rof detiaw eh os
.emit eht fo hcum sessalgeye raew ot yrassecen ti dnuof dah eh sraey tnecer ni hguoht
sevooh dna swap sa
”.uoy romuh ot gnilliw m’I tuB
.thgin eht rof ni delttes yeht sa
.taht ta detseretni dekool ardnoS
,ekahs doog a morf tsuj ylecin delttes netfo ti taht hguone esraoc saw ruf nwo siH
.derepsihw eh ”,evigrof
”.gnissarrabme fo dnik saw tI
.nees tsuj dah yeht yalp raebsekahS eht morf gnitouq ,derumrum eh ”?em ot efil si tahW“ .eniw sih dna
hU“ .steknalb eht rednu kcab teg ot fi sa edam dna
”.gnola lla uoy rof gnitiaw ereh neeb ev’I
.detaes eb ot enoyreve gnillet fi sa nwod mlap meht denrut dna dewob
.ecalptekram eht morf llihnwod
.elbissop yaw tnecifingam tsom eht ni efil ot sraey wef tsal eht rof ecnamrofrep yreve dna ,egats siht
,nwo s’cenneF naht lacisum erom tub hctip ni rewol tahwemos ,eciov delffum A
”,won srevotfel tuoba gniklat er’eW“
.smle eht rednu ylksirb gnola deklaw yeht sa dias sogrA
”.senocs tnarruc neve ro snub ykcits toh eb thgim erehT
.dehgis xof eht tsal tA
,swodahs eht pu kaerb ot elttil did pmal teerts lanoisacco ehT
.ylwols dias eh ”,ecneirepxe na dab oot eb ton thgim tI“
.mih dniheb ylteiuq ti gnisolc
,liatdeR cenneF dna revaeW sogrA
.puc nwo sih ot yllarebil taht dedda eh dna
,dedda dna delims ardnoS ”.esirprus
,gnicnad eht dna gnineve gnol eht retfa etiteppa na evah ot demees enoyrevE
”.su fo daeha enog lla era snub ykcits esoht erofeb
noitnetni ruo si tI
.tcaf ni ,eno taht rof si yek eht erehw erus ton m’I“
”.ris ,dethgiled eb d’I“
flesti fo hguone thgirb tsomla won saw hcihw ,thgilnoom eht dia ot
.ti tuoba em gnisaet rof uoy evigrof ll’I dnA“ .deddon cenneF
redro eht kcab gnirb pleh ot
,xof eht rof hcum oot yllaer saw sihT
”?yetihW ,ti tuoba woH
”.em htiw yats emoc ot seerga
dehgual dna dedualppa srehto ehT
,elbidua llits saw cisum tnatsid ehT
nit a morf aet denoops dna
llah eht morf deretne yllautca flow eht erofeb hcaorppa s’dneirf sih decnuonna
.dehgis dna redluohs s’flow eht tsniaga denael cenneF
.shtnom rof uoy nees t’nevah eW !yzuS“
.tib a gniggalf eb ot demees dworc eht tub
,hguoht ,desirprus t’nsaw eH
eenk eht no dneirf sih dettap sogrA
”.won revir eht nwod retaw lla s’tI
,cenneF ta tsrif delwocs sogrA
”’,oN‘ gniraeh fo derit tsuj m’I
.niaga nwod tas dna deggurhs cenneF
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
esolc dneirf sih gnigguh yb dednopser sogrA
.dekoj cenneF ”,ecivres emoS“
,ffo gnilooc si rehtaew eht taht woN“ .derewsna sogrA
.woleb secaps fo swor dna
peels ll’ew dna em htiw emoC
,pu tnew niatruc eht erofeb hceeps gnimoclew feirb eht morf flow eht detcartsid ylraen esirprus ehT
.sselesu gnihtemos xof dlo evitanigaminu na hcaet ot denimreted si sogrA ,wonk uoy ,lleW“
pu gninaelc ylisub erew srehto dna dnabsuh s’yzuS erehw
.bos ot nageb dna sogrA ot gnulc eh sa
,meht ni oga sraey ynam morf tik gnuoy eht fo tnih a yllautca saw erehT
,telecarb sih no dekraps
ynapmoc gnitca ruo derutrun evah dna
”.daetsni knurd eb em teL“
,won krad erew krow ’sogrA rof thgilyad dedivorp taht swodniw hgih ehT .moor mid eht ni
,llew sa top cimarec a htiw edommoc a saw ereht wenk cenneF
.ezeerb gnineve etal eht ni teerts eht no gnidnats sevlesmeht dnuof yeht dna
”?ew llahs ,kcab s’neeuQ eht dniheb gnittolp saw gniK eht tahw tuo dnif s’tel woN“
”?yeht t’nod ,tsaf os pu worg yehT“
,rehcaet tseb eht saw ehS“
.deknilb dna denway cenneF
.thguoht eh ,yadrutaS
ecalptekram eht ni lavitsef tsevrah eht morf cisum ecnad fo niarts tniaf A
,eniw dna ela eht yojne ot kcab tas
.rednerrus I“ .dias eh
.gnihtemos ro suoiriled eb tsum uoY“
.ecalp cilbup a ni noitceffa fo noitartsnomed a hcus edam dah xof eht taht saw emit tsal eht nehw kniht t’ndluoc eH
.deb ym ni si won thgir peels ot ecalp ylno eht tuB
reward a morf snoops revliS
.dneirf gnolefil a htiw swap gnidloh ot noitcejbo on dah ylniatrec eh tub
pu dehcaer eH ”?ardnoS ,ew t’noW“
,neht pu ekops cenneF
,sedaced rof sdneirf esolc neeb evah
nehctik llams eht otni dna
,delkcuhc flow ehT
,dnim sih hguorht dessap thguoht eht sa neve tub
.ksed eht ssorca ti dial d’eh erehw morf kcits sih pu dekcip cenneF
,raebsekahS morf etouq rehtonA
,retsam eht er’uoy won dnA
”.em morf snoitalutargnoc s’ereh os
nottahC ni nwod dliug ruoy rof retsam eht gniyalp erew uoy elihw ereh enola gnieB
.sogrA ta dekool lemmaH
!kcA“ .pu doots dna
”?niaga hcaet ot kcab gniog eb uoy lliW“
.nwod tas dna loots eht tuo dellup eH
,retnuoc krow a no tas taht eno regral eht morf elttek llams a gnilliF
.woble s’flow eht ta deggut dna pal s’cenneF ssorca denael ardnoS
tuo htaerb sih tel cenneF
.tnelat ylevil a dah dna ti deyojne ylraelc xof ehT
”?ydal denodnaba roop
,yltnatcepxe mih dehctaw ecneidua ehT
.ti fo retteb thguoht t’nevah I“
”.oot syalp etirovaf ym fo eno si thgiN nmutuA na fo maerD ehT
,etunim a rof neve desuap I emit yreve
”.tsael ta tnegru gnihtoN“
ruoh retrauq rehtona nI
,demmid aera gnitaes eht detanimulli taht sthgilsag evitavonni eht nehW
”?uoy t’nod ,netfo reh fo kniht llits uoY“
”.wolleF dooG ylloJ a s’eH roF“ gniyalp artsehcro llams eht dna
pu gnidnats erofeb
.thgir ylbaborp er’uoY“ .denway cenneF
.trats eht ssim ll’ew ,nom’C“
.revo deirruh norpa na gniraew tibbar ylnortam A .nwod tas dna
:yojne esaelP  ".retteb steg tI"
”.sgge evah yeht fi yllaicepsE“ .esuap trohs A
”,ris ,dnammoc ym si hsiw ruoY“
knis eht yb kcar eht morf lewot nenil a dellup eH
,erif a dliub ot detrats dna evotsdoow eht ot denrut eH
”,elzzum ym esnir nac I os erom tib a pmuP“
”.sogrA revaewretsaM fo ecneserp eht ni ton ,tsael tA
ecalp nekat dah tekram ylhtnom eht revo etupsid rojam A
”,detseggus sah sogrA sa ,emitdeB“
.yetihW ,thgin lla uoy htiw gnieb tsuj sa suoiciled sa gnihtoN“
.ti eveileb nac uoy fi ,nwot fo tuo yllautca saw I“
,trapa gnipeels fo sraey ytriht ylraen retfa neve taht dnif ot desirprus saw rehtieN
”.snosam kcirb dna ,sreretsalp ,sretneprac eht ot nwod
.thgin ta yllaicepse ,dekcol rood nedrag eht tpek syawla ew tuB
.retnec eht ni tnelis tas mool eht dna
.sguh yldneirf htiw ardnoS deteerg dna
,cenneF naht rellat sehcni fo elpuoc a saw sogrA
.cenneF ta ecnalg a laets did sogrA
.rae s’cenneF otni derumrum eh
.ylmrif dias xof eht ”,oN“
nwo sih ni wap s’cenneF koot eH
retaw gnihsug dloc eht rednu ecaf sih dekcud sogrA dna ,deilpmoc cenneF .dias eh
”.ti timda t’now uoy hguoht neve
deb eht fo edis eht ffo teef sih deppils eH
.derotser sretcarahc eht neewteb spihsnoitaler eht dna
efas ti tpek ev’uoy ,yletanutroF .oga sraey ynam
.ti erahs ot eno on dna
.em mlehwrevo uoy
neeuQ flE eht deyalp ohw nooccar ehT
.derewsna flow eht
,egats eht no desucof eb ot demees noitnetta lluf s’xof ehT
esiwrehto dias wap sih tub
.sredluohs dna kcen sih dettep dna
.reh dehsuhs eh dna
.kcalc eltneg a htiw senots gnivap eht ni ssennevenu na tsniaga ti fo pit eht tes eh neht dna won tub
”?rolrap ym otni emoc uoy t’noW“
,htoob doof eht ot kcab sparcs dna sehsid eht yrrac depleh enoyreve
spup naht erom elttil erew yeht nehw gninnigeb
.dias sogrA ”,ereh era yeht
.swodahs teerts eht ni doots yeht sa
,dnah ta esolc doots selbaT
”,tsoL ruobaL s’efiL od yeht nehw htnom txen yleruS“
.siht ta taorht sih deraelc lemmaH
”.tcaf ni ,ylbirreT .uoy dessim I
.gnirewsna erofeb eniw sih ta deppal
.ereh saw rezaM nehw peels ot desu I erehw tfol eht ot skoob ym tfihs nac I .t’nseod ti woN
”?dnatsrednu t’nod llits uoy ,raed roop ym ,deR“ .deksa eh
.elbat eht no tes yeht hcihw
.peels emos teg neht dna aet ruo evah s’teL“ .ti derevoc dna
”.esruoc fo ,renoos ton fI“ .derewsna cenneF
.taht deredisnoc cenneF
selsia eht pu delffuhs
.mih tsniaga xof eht gnidloh ,swollip eht otni erom ecno dexaler eh dna
ynoclab eht fo tnorf eht ta staes raluger dah ruof lla tub
,trap ym enod ev’I
,peelsa saw xof eht taht erus saw sogrA
esualppa fo rednuht a ot niaga nwod tas eH
.flesruoy ot ylno tub ,sey ,leurc erew uoY
.ylevissessop ,mih revo mra eno tup sogrA dna
.retal siht tuoba erom klat nac eW“ .dias sogrA
niaga pu delruc xof ehT
,hctah ot dewolla erew sgge ’sneh esoht lla fi tuB
.uoy fo esuaceb oga sraey evif laedro taht devivrus I ,deR“
,derevoc-llew erew tsom hguoht
.noos gnitrats eb lliw yllaS dna ,won loohcs ni era ytteB dna ylliB
.elpuoc tacbob eht ta delims sogrA
.eulB no eulB dna
”?niaga teem ruof ew llahs nehw dnA“ .deerga eh
.gnilkraps seye sih
.aet eht ruop ot pu doots dna
erauqs ecnad yraropmet a detanimulli thgilhcroT
”,yllis ,wob a ekat dna pu dnatS“
,tseb eht era uoy,sogrA“
.deR ,rehtie taht ot tcejbo t’now ylniatrec I ,won ti tuoba yltnereffid leef uoy fi dnA
,rehto hcae gnilcric selpuoc wef a llits erew erehT
.decnuonna ehs ”,tca dnoces eht rof pu tes ew elihw
.rehtie ti dekcol reven rezaM
,kcab dna pu nward erew sniatruc eht sA .srehto ot kool
,srufeltneg deriter-imes sa meht ees ew ereH
.drah dna dloc teg lliw snub ykcits esoht ,wap rehto eht nO“
.noos flesmih tnemeriter rof pu gnimoc dna
.talf ynit taht ni yats ot uoy rof deen on s’ereht ,deR ,yllaeR“
,orevO ovitlA ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb ”emoH tsevraH“
.ylluftsiw derewsna sogrA
.gnihcaet fo tib a od dna nottahC ot nwod emoc ot em deksa dliuG ehT
.niaga flesmih detaes neht eH
,niaga tpels eh dnA
”.riaffa ecivres-fles a fo erom syawla saw tneve siht thguoht I
”?neht og ew llahS
noissimretni tsrif eht rof llef niatruc eht sa ,revewoH
”.timmad ,wob rehtona ekat dna pu dnats woN
.dneirf ym ,ot uoy dednetni tbuod on ehs sA“
”.hguorht lla ti kniht ot em decrof
.eno etihw regral sih htiw wap kcalb a derevoc dna
,gnidliub llams eht ni sexob etavirp on erew erehT
.dias eh ”,edisni uoy eeS“
.setunim wef a rof ria gnineve hserf eht ekat ot
,taht dnA .sraey ytfif ylraen rof traeh ym ni tlewd ev’uoy tey
.llorts rieht demuser yehT
.evigrof ot flesruoy ylno evah uoy dna
”.os yas uoy fi ,thgir llA“
?ti t’nseod ,pu uoy sekaw ti tuB“ ”.ehca eson ym sekaM“ .denialpmoc xof eht ”,dloc si tahT“
,ocitrop daorb eht ni dna teerts eht no dnuora doots elpoeP
.tnemom a rof nikpan a htiw delddif dna
.kcab lewot pmad eht dednah cenneF
.doof eht gnivres fo daetsni elbat eht ta tis yllautca uoy ees I taht netfo t’nsi tI
.sogrA ,aedi enif A“
.uoy evol I hcum woh uoy ot dettimda reven ev’I“ ,derumrum eh
,smaxe gnivig dna gnihcaet htiw saw I sa ysuB
.taes sih ni nwod gnihcnurcs yb edih ot gniyrt
wap s’tacbob eht koot ehS
”?ydaer tuoba uoy erA“
’.sselesu‘ krow sih gnillac yb drab raeb eht tlusni t’nac uoy wonk uoy“ ,dekoj lemmaH
”.niaga ereh evil emoc ot uoy ksa neve t’now I
,dias flow eht ”,gnorw toN“
.ylluferac ti dnuora deklaw eh sa
.srae rieht dehcaer
rood oiduts eht hguorht tuo xof eht del dna
”.gnirons s’rehto hcae dnats llits nac ew fi tuo dnif s’teL
.moor eht ni swodahs gnol tsac
.redluohs s’flow eht otni elzzum sih dehsup dna
.yletanoitceffa rae s’etam sih dekaewt dna
”?od ot deen ew gnihtynA“ .derumrum eh
.dennirg dna dessih ehs
”,ronoh ruoy ,woN“ ”.era ew ereh oS
.neeb evah dluoc reven ereht
aet eht knard yeht sa
eht ni elA .yzuS ssiM dna flow etihw gninrecsid ruo rof sehciwdnas sserc dna rebmucuc
htmraw emoclew eht htiw denibmoc tca tsrif eht yojne ot taes sih ni kcab delttes flow ehT
.gnikab neeb evah mom reh dna einnA teb ll’I
.cenneF ot txen ecalp sih otni deppord eh erofeb
,spuc tuo gnirb ot pu tog sogrA neht dna
”.ti ezilaer ot mees t’ndid uoy nehw neve ,neeb syawla sah emoh ruoy erehw si sihT
”.tpecca ot detpmet m’I ssefnoc I
.tib a gnitnap dna gnihgual
,em rof esle enoyna reven saw erehT
htab nit a laever ot nepo doots llah eht fo dne eht ta rood driht ehT
.gnidnuof sti morf esuoh arepo eht rof draob eht no tas dah ardnoS dna
ereh moor hcum os evah I
.ynoclab eht ni neht dna
,dna snoitcennocretni rieht gnipoleved
,og s’tel woN .nrobbuts tsuj“
elavtseW fo tnediser emitgnol
.sogrA ta dekniw ehS
,sretroppus tseb ruo ronoh ot esuoh eht fo ybbol eht ni gnah lliw hcihw ,euqalp siht no raeppa ot eman tsrif ehT“
revaew ehT ”?ot pu neeb uoy evah tahW
eciwt deppar dna
,ecalp ytpme dna dloc a mees yam tI“ .derepsihw eh
”.noos yrev thgin eht rof tiuq ot gniog ylbaborp er’yehT ?ton yhW“
topaet eht dellif ylluferac eh ,gnas elttek eht nehW
.deb erofeb eniw emos dna kcans taht rof ydaer m’I“
”.staes ruoy ekat nac uoy os niaga sesir niatruc eht erofeb setunim eerht lleb eht dnuos lliw eW
.eunitnoc t’ndluoc tub
”.noitubirtnoc s’enoyreve ronoh ot yaw etairporppa na mees seod tI
”.won tiaw tub od ot gnihtoN“
”.yalp eht ssim ot tnaw t’nod I
.uoy htiw emoh gniog m’I“
noitelpmoc ot maerd a gniees rof
,erom elttil a mraw ot deunitnoc nehctik eht dna
.sogrA ,ti tnaw uoy fi ,lliw ew esruoc fo ,seY“
”.sdneirf ym gnoma emoh kcab eb ot yppah m’I dna
noissimretni etunim neetfif a eb lliw erehT“
lemmaH htiw swap depsalc htob cenneF dna sogrA
,yad txen eht rof yawa sgniht gnittup dna
”.owt ro eno tae uoy fi deed doog a sa ti tnuoc ll’I os
.rewsna ot eno eht saw cenneF
,edisbus ot nageb mrots eht nehW
moorkrow eht hguorht dneirf sih dediug yltneg eh
uoy fo eno yreve dna hcae knaht ylbmuh I
”.gninrom yb retteb leef ll’uoy kniht I
ecnelis ni tas yehT
.pis a koot dna yzuS dna lemmaH ot ssalg eht desiar eH
redluohs s’cenneF no dewollip won saw daeh sih taht dnuof flow ehT
teef sih ot ylidob mih gnillup dna mra s’xof eht rednu wap a gnidils ,rae s’dneirf sih delzzun dna ni denael tub ,rewsna t’ndid flow ehT ”?uoy t’nera ,reve sa lagurF“ .denialpmoc cenneF ”,wodahs tub gnihton si ecalp elohw ehT“
eciov raelc a ni daer ehs
regdel knalb a teg ot gniog ma I tuB