;der ni enodnu dlrow sti ,nus gnittes raeN
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
-- dlrow eht deifeD
yrteop sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,nevaeh ot ssik htiw ,hserf nehW
;hsal a hcus yb desahp erew stsaeb ynam tuB
,evil ot evloseR
noitcerruseR“ .II
.tseuqnoC_divroC ta
saw sihT     .nruter uoy
,ssilb fo dlrow re’O -- ria ot ekat uoy
-- reyarp gnimees elituf taht
”htaeD roF seraperP
,delf tirips sti edam dah gnireffus woH
ekops yeht sa roF
-- slevarnu lliw elttil sti ,llits detsuahxE
meop a uoy gnidaer m’I yadoT dna
gniveileb tsen ynroht ni tser sti edam tI
,saxeT ni gnidiser
drib dèsruc dna kcalb eht ,lla yb deineD
-- slevart dègniw sselmia ni no rednaw oT
,gnignilc -- worros ruoy evael dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
yrruFoS dna ytiniffA ruF no
.drow sti rof tnemegduj eht fo dèvreseD
,”sgnoS-driB natilcareH“   yojne esaelP
-- gnignirps niatnuof sa ,nruom stirips eht daetsnI
;defnu emarf sti seirc sisirc ni ,delixE
”driB natilcareH ehT fO
tserc a htiw detniap dnA
gnihsilbuP gnoseryF rof rotide na dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gniveirg dna niap fo gnap eht nihtiw desacnE
.draeh yeht lla gnitpurroc
.daed eht sflugne emalf gnitsriht eht ,delifeD
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
-- thgilf lufepoh ni skaerb woN  nru ehT !kaorc suoyoj htiw ekowa suht uoY
,drusba dnal morf dih revir egavas yB
-- stsaeb eht deriapseD
,xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb
,gnivieced gnas taht
driB natilcareH ehT“ .I
.hsalc dluow lios eht nihtiw liot ruoy ,deransnE
,nrub taht sdlrow eht tuohtiw
-- nrut latem eht swolla ymehcla ekiL
margeleT no puorg skroW nettirW yrruF eht rof nimda na si ohw
:hsa ni ,htrib ruoy thguorb taht ,htrae ot nruteR
xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb yrteop
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
-- gnignir tiuq seton eseht tsal ta -- won tnelis sdnuoS gnignis ruoy
;gniveihca sti reven erew evol fo sdraweR
.hsarc s’nerhterb ta nrot os
,llewnu desiar dna ,lleh ruoy edisnI
,xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb ”sgnoS-driB natilcareH“