.meht ta derats tsuj rehtaf siH
,edirP yppaH
.tnelis llef moor ehT
.era syawla uoy esroh gnizama emas eht eb d’uoY“  .delims ffeJ
seye s’niveK teem ot pu dekool eH
.delims ehS  ”.tisiv ruoy yojne uoy epoh od I
.tsehc sih otni ecaf reh gnisserp dna gnilims
”.lla si ,htiw devlovni si nos ruo elpoep fo dnik tahw wonk ot tnaw tsuj I ,lleW“
.daeh sih detlit ffeJ
.pu gnitniop srae sih ,deksa niveK
slaudividni seiceps snart tuoba swen eht ni seirots esoht syawla erew ereht llits neve tuB
”?naem ot desoppus taht si tahW“
.sesroh rehto eht lla ekil eb tsuj ot hcum os dna
,deb otni delttes yeht sa
.yletilop delims eH
.rettam tnereffid yleritne na saw nosrep ni tcaer dluow yeht woh tub
.remmah a htiw dehsams dah enoemos rewolf latem detsiwt a ekil dekool ti ytilaer ni tub
.deksa eh ”?I od ,ot evah I“
.ti ot desu teg ot emit deen tsuj stnerap ruoY
.pu nworg d’eh erehw esuoh eht sdrawot yaw rieht edam dna
,nos reh dnuora meht depparw dna smra reh nepo werht ehS
.mih dnuora mra sih depparw eH
.deksa ffeJ ”?mom ruoy dnA“
”.erihsliW .srM ,uoy teem ot erusaelp A“
,uoy teem ot erusaelP“
”.em htiw ereh t’nerew uoy fi od d’I tahw wonk t’nod I  .sknahT“
”?kroY weN ni sgniht era woh ,oS“
”.siht rof uoy evag I gnihtyreve pu evag uoy yhw wonk ot tnaw I“
no tliub era seirots ruo srohpatem lamina eht semitemoS
”,retteb enog evah dluoc tI“
thgin eht fo dne eht ta dna
.emit gnol a rof ,dedneterp I
”.ecnahc a mih evig ll’uoy fi
,ti tnaem eh dna ,dias eh
,rehtom ruoy llits m’I
.dednopser erihsliW .srM
”.uoy htiw ereht thgir eb ll’I dnA“
gnilenap nedoow htooms htiw derevoc erew sllaw eht fo ruof llA
.reh ot pu dellac ,elims gniwonk a mih gnireffo ,ffeJ ”?nwod emoc I yaM“
,dnaherofeb seitilibisnopser eht lla tuoba klat uoy erus ekaM“
.dnah reh ssik ot tuo dehcaer eH
,retal siht lla rof emit eb ll’ereht taht erus m’I“
.yldrawkwa deilper eh
niveK wen eht wonk ot teg ot yrt tsael ta ll’yeht
”,emit ti eviG“  .dias ffeJ
,sreviR neruaL yb ”dootsrednU dna dreH“ saw sihT
.edisni no emoc uoy fo owt eht t’nod yhw ,lleW“  ”.yah ekil sesroh
.ereht pu sgniht esoht dias evah t’ndluohs I wonk I“
tsuj gniht eritne ehT
.tnelis deyats niveK
”?delttes teg ew litnu tiaw ti naC“  .mlac
.devil reyrd dna rehsaw eht erehw moor reliob eht ot rehto eht dna
.derebmemer eh sa hcum ytterp saw tnemesab ehT
,elbatrofmocnu elttil a ffeJ edam sehsid nevlow fo rebmun egral eht llet dluoc eH
.em t’nsaw taht gnihtemoS
.deksa niveK ”?tahw llA“
,erutan ot tnorffa na sa ti deweiv yrtnuoc eht fo straP
.elbadaernu tsomla ,sselnoisserpxe saw ecaf siH
”.ylimaf eht otni stif eh woh yltcaxe gnidiced erofeb
hguone delffum saw ti desolc rood eht ecno yllufknahT
,tnemom a rof nos sih ta derats erihsliW .rM
”.ylekalB ffeJ si eman yM“
”?emit elohw eht em htiw eb ll’uoY“  ”.esimorp I“
”?niaga siht hguorht og ot gniog ew erA“
.lanoitidart ytterp s’daD
.ecaf sih fo tuo riah yarts a gniwolb erofeb dnoces a rof mih ta dekool rehpoT  ”.won esroh a m’I“
.desimorp niveK ”,mom ,lliw eW“
.gel sih no dnah sih decalp eH
noitisnart sih tuoba rehtaf sih ot ekops niveK
?owt uoy tuoba lla su llet uoy t’nod yhw oS“
.sriats eht fo pot eht sdrawot pu daeh reh dehctaw dna delims eH
”.tuo ti krow dluoc owt uoy wenk I“  .delims erihsliW .srM
”.saw I ohw eb ot gniyrt naht ni gnidnelb reisae saw ti esuaceb tub
”?yako ,elbat eht rednu dnah ym ezeeuqs tsuj ,uoy eucser ot em deen uoy fi dnA  .esruoc fO“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
keehc eht no kcil ylregnig eno mih evag ehS  ”.mom ,yawa kciL“
.ysae eb ot gniog t’nsi ti tub
edur mees ton thgim sevlow rehto ot elihw
,repmujwohs noipmahc a sa flesmih ot derrefer eh
”.em fo detcepxe enoyreve tahw eb ot evah t’ndid I taht dnA“  .esuap A
.ereht pu dias dnabsuh ym tahw rof sterger tserecnis ym reffo tsum I“
,yrots eht dlot dad sih sA
.gniht erom eno od ot dah eh
.ylimaf sih wonk ot ecnahc dnoces a nevig neeb dah eh taht
.raef fo tuo ti dediova elpoep emoS .tuo dnif dna
.nehctik eht morf tuohs stnerap sih gniraeh
”.uoy wen eht wonk ot gnitteg pleh emos deen thgiM …tsuj I  .egnahc
nac yeht gnihtyreve od ot gniyrt elpoep fo derit m’I
.mih tub enoyna tceffa t’ndid
.sevooh sih ta nwod dekool niveK
,dnatsrednu ot hsiw ton od ohw esoht htiw laed tsum ew nehW
.remrahC eniuqE eht
raelc era yeht ,semitemos tuB
.seiceps rehto ot drawkwa tib a erew
,buc a saw eh ecnis revE
”.gniod er’uoy gnitcayalp sihT  !sihT“
,wenk stnerap sih htoB
,od ot tahw uoy llet t’nac I“  .deggurhs ffeJ
,soidutS ecnecsedirI yb nooM eulB fo rohtua
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.tuo ti gnirb uoy depleh tsuj I  .ereht ni ydaerla saw uoy laer ehT“
.uoy wen eht tuoba lla em llet uoy t’nod yhw oS“
.meht teerg ot enoemos eb dluow ereht depoh dah niveK fo trap a
ton s’tI“  .deggurhs eH
paehc saw ytreporp ecnis
.mih ta derats niveK
,mom ,seY“  .deddon niveK
.sevooh rieht rednu teprac yerg etals a htiw
delims eH  ”.mom ,sknahT“
.liat esroh dna ,srae deretla
.ffeJ sdrawot derutseg eH
,esoprup no ti od dluow meht fo rehtien esruoc fO
”?ti t’nsi ,gniht emas eht rof sdrow tnereffid tsuj s’ti kcap a ro dreh a s’ti rehtehw ,kooL
.rehtaf sih yllaicepse
.yadhtrib s’dnabsuh reh rof laem citsatnaf a gnikooc tuo lla enog dah rehtom sih tbuod oN
.yawrood eht morf deraeppasid dah rehtaf sih deciton dna
.ylimaf eno teg ylno uoy tub
.sevooh sih ot gnitteg
”.emit erom elttil a siht evig dluohs uoy kniht I tuB  .og ll’ew
.rennacs evaw retemillim eht gnitarepo nosrep eht yb netfo tsom
”,enim si erusaelp ehT“
,dellac mom sih ”!niveK“  .rentrap sih wollof ot gnivom erofeb erihsliW .srM ta ylsselpleh dekool ffeJ
”.em ees yeht litnu meht ot laer eb ot gniog ton s’ti
.emahs fo erutseg enipul a ni derewol dna talf srae sih
,eb thgim ti thguoht yeht diputs woh rettam on taht meht gnirussaer ,snoitseuq rieht derewsna eh sa
etadpu ot sgniht ynam os ,og ot tfel spets rehto erew erehT
edis sih ta ecneserp s’ffeJ tlef dna delims niveK
.demaeb ffeJ ”,em s’tahT“
ytilibissop eht tnorfnoc ot decrof saw eh
.noitisnart rieht tpecca ot desufer taht ylimaf dah elpoep ynam os yhw saw ti desoppus eH
”,nwod mih dnes ,thgir llA“
remlac mih gnikam wohemos
trap tsom eht roF
.sriats eht pu yaw rieht edam sesroh owt eht ,dniheb gniwolloF
.t’nsi ti ,oN“ ”.yako s’ti ,niveK“
ssalc yrotsih tra sih ot gnidroccA
”.yadhtrib hteitrof s’rehtaf ruoy s’tI
pu hctac ot dlrow eht fo tser eht rof gnitiaw fo derit saw mih fo trap a tuB
.elbissop eb ton thgim stnerap sih htiw ytitnedi wen sih gnilicnocer taht
.nwo sih revo dils taht repahs elzzum eht dna
efil sih degnahc dah ti hcum woh dna
.htiw trap ot raeb t’ndluoc
aera ruo ni tneced era secirP
.ti teg t’nod tsuj I tub
.htaerb peed a tuo gnittel ,dehgis niveK
”.tpmetta eht htrow s’ti
.smra sih ni ffeJ decarbme dna egaggul sih nwod tes eh ,tsal ta enolA
”,dad ,oot uoy evol I“
”?aedi doog a s’taht erus uoy erA“
.ffeJ ot gninrut ,dias eh ”,yakO“
.sevooh larutan fo ssendrah dna kool eht etacilpud ot dengised
.esiwrehto ro yllanoitnetni
.nos sih ot ti dednetxe eh erofeb wap a htiw kcen sih fo kcab eht debbur dna yldrawkwa detfihs erihsliW redle
,erats napdaed a mih gniviG  ”.siht llA“
.niaga ecno taes sih koot niveK
”dootsrednU dna dreH“
”…ot tcaer ot gniog era stnerap ym woh wonk t’nod tsuj I“
,did syawla eh yaw taht ni redluohs sih degassam ffeJ
.ffeJ ta dekool dna dehgis niveK
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.orb ,yrgnuh er’uoy epoh I“  .deohce rehpoT
”.ffeJ si sihT  .si eH“
”…tub ,dluow uoy taht wonk I ,naem I“
,renroc eht ni esactius sih ta gniratS
.stnap esoht otni deruop pu thgiarts dekool noillats eht ,snaej dna trihs lausac a ni desserD
.ssecorp elohw eht fo tcepsa detacilpmoc tsom eht neeb dah srae sih fo epahs eht retla ot yregrus ehT
.elbat eht dnuora gnirehtag ylimaf reh fo thgis eht ta erutsiom htiw ytsim seye reh ,delims ehS
,pets gib a si ni gnivom wonk uoY“
.yrotciv a eb dluow ti ylrae kcab gniylf tuohtiw
”.niaga yrots taht ton ,on ,hO“  .denaorg rehpoT .deksa eh
,noitacifitnedi sih no degnahc seiceps sih dah yllagel tsuj d’eH
,puorg eht fo tser eht ot gnillac redael kcap a fo dnuos eht fo mrofevaw eht saw ti
”?tnemtrapa tsrif ruo tuoba uoy llet reve I diD“
”.no pu hctac ot hcum os tog ev’eW
,tneconni eht tcetorp ot saw ti gnitsisni srehto htiw
.deinnihw yltneg dna seson rieht dehcuot owt ehT
.nehctik eht otni deraeppasid mom rieht sa
elbat eht no sehsid fo elpuoc tsal eht gnicalp rehtorb sih htiw
.uoy si sihT“  .deksa eh
.noos ytterp rehtegot ni gnivom tuoba gnikniht er’ew ,lleW“
.delworg erihsliW .rM
,noisiced eht ot emac eno woh rettam oN
deneppah tsuj dah tahw nevig tub
.og gnittel erofeb kcab eht no eciwt mih gnittap
,delahxe dna riap eht ot pu deklaw dad siH
.denrael elpoep woh saw siht taht
.denepo tnemesab eht ot rood eht sa pu dekrep srae riehT
pets tsrif taht ekat ot ydaer erew yeht rehtehw ot sa noitseuq taht syawla saw ereht
.noillats gnuoy ,emoh ruo ot emocleW“
.relpmis tol a saw dlrow eht pup a saw I nehw kcaB  .taht wonk uoY
.enalp eht draob ot emac tnemecnuonna eht ,taht htiw dnA
,siht gniwonk neve teY
,mih detcerroc eh ”,denoitisnart I“
”.ydaer er’ew kniht I tub
.mra s’dneirfyob sih no dnah a gnidloh
.won uoy sevol ehs ,tneve yna nI“  .deilper eh
.hcuoc eht fo htgnel eht decap eH  ”.yrros m’I“
.nam ,hcum os uoy dessim ev’I“
,snoitcerid efas emos ni noitasrevnoc eht reets tsael ta ot rehtom sih no yler dluoc eh wenk eH
,sreviR neruaL yb
,dewollof taht gniugra eht ot netsil ton did eH
.liated yreve ot denetsil ylregae eh sa
”.hsilpmocca ot gniog si thgin rehtona tahw wonk t’nod I“
.noitcerid rehtona ni noitasrevnoc eht trevid ot detpmetta rehtom siH
.dlohesuoh lanoitidart yrev a ni pu werg I
tuo ti erugif ot reisae tol a s’tI“
”.gniht esroh a yllaer
.esruoc fo ,thgir saw eh wenk niveK
.deksa eh ”?on hO“  .dias niveK
.skcirt wen emos nrael t’nac I naem t’nseod
.era uoy tahw em ot rettam t’nseod ti lleW“
,evlove dna nrael ot gnilliw erew emoS
.deddon niveK .dias eh
?saw eh fi ekam ti dluow ecnereffid tahW
rac a tner ot meht fo owt eht rof neeb dah nalp ehT
.sretrauq yraropmet rieht ot ni elttes ot meht tfel eh
,tib a retaw htuom sih ekam did sllems eht fo emos ,tsenoh gnieb saw eh fI
,buc a neeb dah eh nehw sa emas eht saw hcuoc ehT
?flow a ton dna esroh a yllagel saw eh fi tahw oS
.denworf mom siH  ”.thgir ,hO“
”.deraperp ton er’uoy fi detacilpmoc laer teg nac taht gniht fo dnik eht s’ti emit gnol a rof gnitad neeb ev’uoy fi neve
,mih htiw klat doog a dah I tub ,esucxe on s’taht wonk I woN
reve t’now trap tahT
.hsop hsip hO“ ”.su elddoc ot evah t’nod uoY“
.rehtaf sih morf yawa denrut niveK
no tniop siht morf taht gniwonk
”.tnaem I tahw ton s’tahT“
ehT	     .troffe eniuneg s’rehtaf sih gnisnes
,erac yeht wonk I“
.roolf dnuorg eht sdrawot sriats eht pu kcab yaw eht del erihsliW .rM
,eb ot detnaw yeht tahw eb ot yhtrow erew yeht ton ro rehtehw ot sa noitseuq ehT
”.pu deinop uoy ,eurt s’ti oS  !orb ,yeH“
.riahc reh ni kcab denael ehs sa delims erihsliW .srM
”.elbatrofmoc teg dna ni elttes os rennid litnu ruoh na tuoba evah eW“
.neht thgir gniwonk dad htiw laed ot detnaw I fi erus t’nsaw I dna eciohc eht reh dereffo I esuaceb ti did I
,esroh niht a fo tib A
emit eht fo tsom tub
.erow reve eh tiftuo yreve yllacitcarp ni gnizama dekool taht
sseflow doog a yrram dluow eh nehw yad eht ot drawrof gnikool dna
”.mom ,enif eb ll’ew erus m’I“
,tol a ti tuoba deklat ew dna sraey wef a rof gnitad neeb ev’eW“
”.mom ,flesmih rof kaeps ot hguone dlo s’dad kniht I“
”,ereh eb neve dluow uoy fo rehtien tnemtrapa taht rof ton fi ,yeH“
”.eromyna esoht tae yllaer t’nod I  .mu ,hO“
,elbativeni saw ssendrawkwa elttil a tsael ta taht detpecca dah niveK
ffeJ rof edisa eno dellup eh ,sregrubyah fo yart eht rof gnihcaeR
.nwo reh ot yaw eht no riahc sih dessap ehs sa guh mraw a denrae ffeJ nevE
”,enif eb lliw sgnihT“
.evaw keem a ni dnah sih pu dleh eH
mih dnuora smra sih depparw eH
.ylduorp deilper niveK
,sklawedis enotselbboc eht ta nwod dekool dna rood eht denepo eH
.elzzum sih kcil ot ni denael ehS  ”.wal eht s’tI
,esroh a emaceb eh woh dna
,hcuoc eht no despalloc dna tnemesab eht ot nwod yaw sih edam niveK
.edisni htob meht derehsu neht dna
,eye edis eht nevig saw eh
.hgis yvaeh a htiw kcab daeh sih gniworht
”.yppah em sekam tahw si siht dnatsrednu ot evah tsuj uoy tub
”.tuoba gniklat neeb sah niveK ym dneirfyob eht er’uoy oS“
seirots neewteb nI
”.su fo htob eht rof dnim ni tnereffid gnihtemos gnirutcip srieht tneps ev’yehT
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
”,niveK ym ekil llems llits uoy ,hO“
”?esroh laer a ton I mA“
.esucxe on evah I dna
,rekamecaep yalp ot detpmetta ffeJ
,sregnif deppit fooh sih ta dekool eH
.yenruoj eht fo trap ylpmis lla saw dootsrednu eh eno dna
uoy tuoba erac yllaer yeht fI
.emit emas eht ta lla seirrow sih gnihtoos dna
.gnixaler eb ot desoppus er’uoY“
”.tuoba lla si siht tahw wonk ot tnaw I
.deggurhs eh ,dewollaws dah eh ecnO
.wob suoicarg a htiw reh deucser ffeJ
?naem uoy did tahw nehT“
”.eb ot em detnaw uoy tahw si ton m’I tahw tub
.mih ediseb taes a koot ffeJ  .dias niveK
”,mraw llits si doof eht elihw sriatspu kcab og dluohs ew won thgir kniht I tub
,emoh doohdlihc sih ta gnivirrA
,esroh a emaceb eh nehw egnahc dluow sgniht emos taht nwonk dah eh hguohtlA
.esroh a ton ,flow a desiar I“
.sevooh sih ta nwod dekool eH
.rood tnemesab eht ot yaw sih no ydaerla saw eh tub
tub erots ot dehsiw ylimaf eht sgniht rehto dna
”?cibohpsnart gnihtemos yas ot gniog si ylimaf ruoy kniht yllaer uoY“
”.ma’am ,hcum oot nos ruoy tpurroc ot ton yrt ll’I“
.emit tsal eht saw ti gnipoh
.tnemtnioppasid raelc htiw mih ta deralg eH
.dnah sih fo hsiruolf a htiw noissimrep sih dereffo niveK .deksa ehs
.taht ekil sgniht tuoba klat t’ndid tsuj ew ebyam rO
”.kniht I ,ti no gnikrow er’ew tub
lufetarg ,wollip eht no daeh sih detser niveK
renroc eht ni pu tes vt eht htiw
.elzzum sih morf ria fo trons eltneg a mih gnivig
,gnieb saw I dratsab rettu na tahw em dlot mom ruoY
fo erutseg a ni sdnah deppit fooh sih pu dleh niveK
.detcepxe enoyreve tahw s’taht esuaceb flow a saw I“  .dehgis eH
eciov ot diarfa oot neeb syawla dah eh tahw decarbme eh ecnis
.rehtom sih doots pot eht ta dna ,denepo tnemesab eht ot rood ehT
.dniheb ffuts esroh ym lla evael ot em deksa ehs detisiv I emit tsal eht tuB
,hguone ti devresed yeht fi ro
.elims gnigaruocne na mih dereffo rehtom siH
.emoh ylimaf erihsliW eht ot yaw rieht ekam dna
”.ytrap hcraes a sdnes mom erofeb og retteb d’ew sseug I“
.htrib ta uoy ot dengissa eno eht ton saw taht seiceps a sa yfitnedi ot efas morf raf saw ti
”.dad ,oot uoy teem ot eciN“
,detnarg rof koot esle enoyreve sgniht eht gniod ssenisub sih tuoba og ot saw detnaw eh llA
.sgab eht teg ot knurt eht ot gniog ,delims eH
.flow a gnieb yppah t’nsaw I“
”,noonretfa worromot emoh kcab eb dna thgilf ruo egnahc nac eW“ .deerga ffeJ
?esroh a gnieb ekil ti s’tahW
meht teg emoc ot yaw rieht fo tuo emoc ot stnerap sih ksa ot
,pohskrow s’rehtaf sih ot del hcihw fo eno
”,noiger eht hguorht stcudorp etubirtsid ot seinapmoc tnereffid fo tol a htiw krow eW
”.teiuq dna ecaep emos ,yllaniF“
,delims dna dnuora emac ffeJ
”.ffeJ htiw saw I nehw flesym erom tlef syawla I tuB
noom eht fo llac eht tlef I esuaceb toN
,ti fo gnah eht nettog d’eh
,thginot uoy ees ll’yeht ,lleW“
,ytiniffaruF no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.s’niveK no dnah sih gnicalp ,dias eh
”.retal ti tuoba eugra ot evah ot naht
.gninrom eht ni esuoh eht evael ot efas neve saw ti fi
.ereht dna ereh sehsid desab elbategev wef a erew ereht tub
.slaudividni seiceps snart gnoma noitseuq nommoc a saw tI
.gniyrt neeb dah tsael ta rehtorb sih dna
.enod ydaerla saw egamad eht tub
.redluohs sih dezeeuqs dna delims ,ffeJ deman noillats a ,noinapmoc gnilevart siH  .siht saw sA
.dnuora lla erutluc flow fo sngis fo tol a erew ereht hcus sa dna
,ssecorp a saw ti ,esruoc fO
kniwt a tsuj yltsom saw eh
yllufhturt hguohtla
taht od dluoc eh erofeb tub
,tuo ti krow dna yrt ot tohs a neve s’ereht fi ekil smees tI
.egaruoc eht mih nevig dah ffeJ litnu
.dias erihsliW .srM
,stnemtsujda emos eb ll’ereht wonk eW
murtceps a fo erom sa ti gniweiv elpoep tsom htiw
.flesmih ot derutseg eH
”.erihsliW .srM ,tneced er’eW“
,uoy ot pu ti ekam ot yrt ot stnaw eh dna
rehtorb ym llits er’uoY
.lla s’taht ,sgniht ot desu gnitteg emit drah a gnivah tsuj s’eH“
.rac eht fo tuo sgel sih gnuws eh sa tib a gninworf
.sregrub yah emos uoy xif nac I ,lleW“
”.taht retfa ton ,esuoh siht ni yats t’nac I“
,tib a taes sih otni knuls niveK
.erac dluohs enoyna yhw dnatsrednu t’ndid niveK
,rentrap sih ta delims noillats ehT  .dias eh
,nos ruoy llits m’I  .yaw yreve ni
.evisulcni erom tib a gnihtemos rof lavomer sti gnitseuqer tuoba stsetorp neeb dah ereht hguoht
rood eht dleh rehtorb siH
.rehto hcae htiw detcaretni seniuqe woh tuoba mih gnihcaet dna
.tluciffid syawla saw tropria eht hguorht gnilevarT
.demaeb niveK .deksa eh
”.retteb wonk yeht erus ekam ot evah tsuj ll’ew od yeht fi ,lleW“  .dias eh ”,ton epoh I“
”.tnemesab eht ot yaw eht uoy wohs ll’I“
flow doog a s’eH
.dereffo rehtom sih
.ffeJ morf gab sih koot eH
taht sgniht gniyas fo yaw a dah yeht tub
.ereht dna ereh ni dereppep seiceps rehto wef a htiw
ton m’I“ ”.dneirfyob a gnivah em ot desu tog ehs erofeb shtnom koot mom yM
”.esroh emosdnah ym ,uoy retfA“
.yb deklaw ehs sa dnabsuh reh ot tnemmoc tsal reh thguac srae detniop siH
,mih rof laed gib a saw tI
spets wef a nekat dah eh ecnO
”,mom ,esruoc fO“  .dias ehs
.mih ediseb ylteiuq tas eh ,dneirfyob sih rof tuo riahc a gnilluP
”!ereh er’uoY  !niveK“
enipul tnecrep ytneves saw ti os neve tuB
”.sllib eht gnittilps yb yenom evas dluoc I dna eh dna
,rotnem sih dna dneirf sih neeb syawla dah dad sih
”…nylkoorB ni tnemtrapa elttil siht dnuof ew ,tuo gnitrats tsrif erew I dna rehtom ruoy nehw kcab woN“
.uoy evol I dna ,nos ym er’uoY
.sregnif deppit fooh sih ta nwod derats dna tsirw sih debbarg eH
.ecnereffid eht lla edam dah taht dna
nades gnikool ycnaf a detner yeht sa neve detcepxe sa lla saw ti mih derussa ffeJ
,gnuoy erew stnerap sih ecnis yaw gnol a emoc dah seiceps no sweiv s’elpoeP
,elbat nehctik eht ta gnivirrA
.esuoh eht morf degreme rehtom sih sa ylthgirb delims dna
.secafrus nevenu no gniklaw dnah decitcarp a gnieb flesmih ,tuo mih gnipleh
.llew ti dih eh tiderc sih ot tub
,puorg eht fo eno llits er’uoY“
”?dneirfyob eht si siht oS“
”?siht rof kcap ruoy dna swalc ruoy pu evig uoy dluow yhw tub
,uoy evol I“
.elims eguh a htiw noillats tuntsehc eht sdrawot dekool eH
.sesu sti sah ytiugibmanu ,neht tuB
,noitarbelec eht rof od ot hcum os saw ereht nehw
mih dnuora dlrow eht tuoba lla mih gnihcaet
.boj ym ekil I dna ,ydaets si krow ,doog er’yehT“  .deksa rehtom sih
.ylimaf a fo sdnob eht detset ylurt dna
.dlot I eno tsrif eht saw ehS
”.nos ,gniklat peeK“
.uoy wen eht teem ot saw I thguoht I sa deraperp sa t’nsaw tsuj I sseug I
sesimorpmoc ekam ot evah eh dluow semit ynam woh tub
.deggurhs eH  ”.hcruhc ta uoy deef yeht ffuts agemO dna ahplA taht lla
.sap xuaf a dettimmoc dah ehs rehtehw no niatrecnu tib a ,ffo deliart ehS
.ydob sih dennacs yeht emit yna seiceps snart saw eh suoivbo saw ti taht wenk eh
.ekahsdnah a mih evig ot troffe na ni smra sih ni sgab eht detfihs yldrawkwa ffeJ
.tirem fo rettam a saw ti fi sa
”,ecin smees ylimaf ruoY“
elbuort fo laed taerg a hguorht enog dah eH
”.uoy ees ot doog nmad s’ti dna
”,melborp eht saw yug a gnieb em erus
”?tuoba ti si tahw nehT“
”?tuo siht thguorb tahW
.sregnif rieht decalretni dna s’ffeJ ot sdnah sih dehcuot niveK
.snoitidart ylimaf eht no yrrac dna
.ti htiw yako eb ot ylimaf sih rof saw detnaw eh lla dna
,citegolopa rehtar dna etirtnoc gnikooL
.yrrufoS dna ,lysaeW
.sriats eht sdrawot meht fo owt eht gnirehsu ,dias ffeJ
,taem no desab erew meht fo tol a esruoc fO
,repahs elzzum sih ta derutseg eH
”?elihw elttil a tiaw tsuj ew t’nod yhW“
”.pu siht wercs t’noD“
.gnidlig-ylil erem noitanalpxe yna gnivael ,suougibmanu dna
:eb ot yaw ylno eht eb nac ssentnulb neht
.tis ot mih egru ot gniyrt wap reh pu dleh rehtom siH  .pu doots niveK
”.taht lla ni em rof moor s’ereht fi wonk t’nod I dna semit drah fo tol a hguorht mih depleh s’tI“
.guh gnirussaer a mih dereffo ffeJ
dna ytlayol kcap tuoba lla s’eH
.tsixe ot thgir eht su yned ot
sbrubus eht ni sesuoh thguob dah elpoep fo sepyt rehto erom dna erom os ytic rojam a morf raf ton erew yeht ylbisnetsO
dlrow tnereffid a ni pu werg I esuaceb tsuj tuB
,em evol llits yeht hguoht neve
.esle gnihtemos was I dna yad yreve rorrim eht ni dekool I
trofmoc gnidnif llits tub sevolg erew yeht gniwonk
”.hguone noillats saw I fi emit eht lla flesym ksa ot desu I ,wonk uoY“
mih ta dekool niveK
.enif ,thgir llA“  .delworg neht dna
stoob fooh sih mih gniwohs
.elzzum sih denepo dna
”.uoy llet ot hcum os tog ev’I
,tey ereht etiuq ton er’eW“
.ecnaraeppa eniuqe rieht ni
.tcejbus elbatrofmocnu eht gnihcaorb ,deksa eh
,yenom yna deen uoy fI“
.nehctik eht morf ni detfaw doof fo sllemS
.flesmih rof rehtona koot dna
meht tsniaga gnihtyna evah t’nod I woN
”.sseug I“  .mih detatirri
mih gnignellahc morf meht tpek snoitcetorp lagel hguohT
.nos tsedle sih morf lloreye na gninrae ,deilper eh
,em rof did uoy gnihtyna terger t’nod I ,daD“
”.emit mih evig tsuJ
.rehtegot sdnekeew ynam tneps dah rehtaf sih dna eh erehw tnemesab eht ot spets eht nwod yaw sih edam ylwols rehtaf sih
.deppots neht dna ,detrats eH  ”…I“
tisiv siht hguorht ti ekam dluoc eh sa gnol sa tub
.flow fo daetsni DI sih no esroh gniees
seciohc efil lanosrep sih taht noitazilaer eht ot
.thgin taht tib a etiuq dnah s’ffeJ gnizeeuqs eb dluow eh gnileef a dah eH  .deilper niveK ”,yakO“ ”.langis ycnegreme ruo ti llac ll’eW“
,og ot syaw a dah llits yeht hguohT
”?kniht uoy od tahW“
”,rehtegot yats ot tnaw d’uoy derugif I ecnis tnemesab eht ni hcuoc gnidlof eht tuo dellup I
sreviR neruaL yb
secalp emos ni tub
,gniliar eht no wap eno htiw sriats eht gnidnecseD
”,dneirfyob trams a tog ev’uoY“
,ysae reven si siht ekil ffutS“  .deggurhs ffeJ
,detaes ydaerla erew stnerap s’niveK
.mra eht no ezeeuqs eltneg a ffeJ evag ehS
”?I t’nera ,nos ym kcil ot dewolla llits ma I“
,stnerap sih morf tnemmoc etivni dluow ti
”?yeht t’nod ,yah ekil sesroH
.flesmih taes a gnikat erofeb
.deksa erihsliW .rM
”.ydaer tsomla s’rennid syas moM  ?tneced uoY“
”?yenoh ,rettam taht seoD“
mih edam ti yppah woh tuoba ekops eH
”.tuo uoy pleh syawla nac I dna dad ruoy
ylevitnetta denetsil ylimaf eritne siH
taht gnileef eht tog I
.ytiruces hguorht gniog fo ssecorp eht dedaerd syawla eh tub
”?dad htiw gnorw gnihtemos sI“
.elbatrofmocnu dnuof yeht sgniht htiw laed ot gnivah morf peek ot yaw a tsuj saw ti
”.edisni flow a t’nsaw I ezilaer em edam eH“
”.llew tnew taht ,lleW“
.sevil elohw ruo ti tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’eW
.ti enod d’eh ecnis emoh gniog emit tsrif sih eb dluow ti dna
,derac eno on trap tsom eht roF
.t’ndluoc ylpmis srehto elihw
.rehto eht ro eno sa ssel dna
.dednetni dah eh naht yllufecrof erom nwod krof sih gnissot ,deksa niveK
”?ynapmoc esroh a siht sI“
.remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer
”,oot uoy teem ot eciN“
ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.erihspmaH weN ni noitanitsed sti ta dednal enalp eht
,guh a meht fo hcae evig ot revo deklaw erihsliW .srM .dias niveK
.nos reh ta delims neht dna
”.yb og uoy eman tahw rettam on
,setirovaf doohdlihc sih fo yna deirt eh fi taht wenk eh tub
rednow uoy edam semitemos taht sgniht dna
.driew tlef ti tuB
.elims citegolopa na dereffo ehs
.ti fo tuo yats ot esohc ,ylesiw ,rehpoT
.deksa eh ”?yako uoy ,veK ,yeH“
”.gniog er’ew erehw teg ew ecno
”.yas ot gnihtemos sah ylraelc eH“
lairetam ekil fooh a htiw deppac dna swalc nwod delif sih gnirevoc ,sevolg erew yehT
.uoy fo owt eht rof ecaps fo ytnelp s’erehT
,gnitpecca yrev neeb dah rehtom siH
.sehsid nevlow lanoitidart eht lla edam dah ehS
,noitasrevnoc dna snoitseuq htiw dellif saw renniD
”dootsrednU dna dreH“
”.uoy teem ot eciN“
ton naht netfo eroM
,deilper niveK ”,rehpoT ,sknahT“
”,dad ,uoy tuoba ton si sihT“
,setalp s’enoyreve dexif dah rehtorb dna rehtom sih
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,srood owt erew moor eht fo edis eht nO
.lwoh s’flow eht tneserper ot tnaem saw taht eutats a saw hcus fo tnenimorp tsom ehT
.elbativeni saw ylimaf sih gnicaf
.mih guh ot drawrof deppets tsael ta rehpoT
.gniyas erew yeht tahw llet ton dluoc eh taht
.swonk ehS  .wonk t’nod I“
,og ot tnaw uoy fI“
.doog erew sloohcs eht dna
”.gnihtyna naem t’ndid rehtaf ruoY“
,thgilf ruoh eerht a retfA
.rehpoT rehtorb redlo sih htiw yawrood eht ni doots rehtaf s’niveK
.ti ot desu ton er’yeht fi yllaicepse
,doohrobhgien detalupop flow yltsom a saw tI
”.mom ,oot uoy evoL“ ”.niveK
,eb ot desoppus saw eh nosrep eht ekil tlef eh tsal ta tuB
.liat sih fo kcilf lufyalp a dna elims evitroppus a dereffo ffeJ
,wenk eh ,lacitcarpmi saw tI
.yrt a htrow s’ti kniht I dna
”.ma I sa esroh a laer sa
.ytiuteprep ni tnaw I revetahw od ot teg I
.sdnah sih gnikat ,delims ffeJ
,emit emos ekat ot gniog saw ti nwonk d’eH
,esle erehwemos ti detcepxe I
,evisneffo gnihtemos yas ton ot ylimaf sih ni decalp eh htiaf hcum woh fo niatrecnu ,deilper niveK
,em ot rettam llits rehpoT dna mom dna uoY
er’uoY“ ?saw yllaer eh ohw tpecca ot ecnatsiser s’elpoep rehto rof
siht gnidnatsrednu emit drah a hcus gnivah m’I yrros m’I
.tib a koot dna regrubyah sih pu dekcip niveK
.dad ,kcap ym pu evag reven I“  .yldas
.tbuod on ,meht rof gnitiaw
,dnopser ot woh niatrecnU .deksa dad sih
.mih ta dekool ffeJ
,nwod mlac ot mih rof noisserpxe gnidaelp a dereffo efiw siH
”.og dluohs ew kniht I  .ekatsim a saw sihT“
”.retteb eb d’uoy depoh d’I tub
”.seotatop dna kaets ,etirovaf ruoy edam moM
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,kcals elttil a dad sih tuc ot detnaw mih fo trap A
.ytinutroppo eht gnizies ,dennirg ffeJ
stoob fooh thgir eht gnidnif
gnimoc saw ti wenk niveK
.hgis peed a tuo tel eh
.yleritne rettam rehtona erew rehtaf sih dna rehtorb sih tub
”.esle gnihtemos uoy ekam t’nseod liat ekaf a dna stoob fooh no gnittuP
.tuoba yrrow ot gnihton saw ereht taht ecnarussaer ecin a neeb evah dluow ti tub
sehtolc dlo htiw dellif sreniatnoc citsalp fo hcnub a dna
.laremehpe dna eltbus era
.dehgis dna tib a srae reh denettalf erihsliW .srM
,kcab eht no tap ylrehtorb a htiw erutseg eht gnitpeccA
”,tnatropmi s’ti kniht t’nod uoy fi neve
,devlovni enoyreve fo tol a deksa tI
,detrats neeb dah noitasrevnoc eht
,noci larutluc tnatropmi na deredisnoc saw ti ,sselehtreveN
”.noitseuq a gniksa tsuj m’I“
.dlrow gnignahc a ot desu gnitteg emit drah a sah eh semitemos tub
.nruter ni ti koohs eh ,dnah sih ni ti gnikaT ”.nos
.sniarb rieht otni deretlif dah taht noisuled emos tsuj ro laer erew sgnileef rieht fi derednow emoS
.spets eht fo tser eht pu gniunitnoc erofeb dnah sih dezeeuqs eH  ”.od yllaer I“
.tnemom a desuap erihsliW .rM
.deilper niveK ”,ton er’uoy oN“
.weiv fo tniop s’rehtaf sih morf degnahc evah dluow hcum woh deredisnoc reven dah eh
.neeb dah ti erehw kcab etalp eht tup ylhsipeehs dna mih gnihctaw dad sih deciton eH