”.tseb eht rof s’ti ebyaM“
.niaga enecs eht maerd uoy ,thgin tahT
;gniwehc hcamots ruoy ni erutaerc a s’erehT
.tsaoC nogerO eht no desab yltnerruc tsigoloib eniram dna retirw a si adoC
.semitemos yrrow I
.ssob ruoy ot liame eht tnes t’nevah uoY
.ti ediseb krap uoy ,mad eht no tuo kcurt sih dnif uoy nehW
.sllaf eht drawot sedilg eH .rehto eht neht
.secalp thgir eht ni skcor eht ecalp ot uoy ediug mih gnittel ,kniht mih gnihctaw devol uoY
.egnahc nac gnihtyna taht
.ezarg swoc s’etats ruoy erehw serutsap eht etagirri ot desu si revir eht morf retaw tub—
,dlihc a ekil leef uoy taht os sredluohs ruoy dnuora smra sih gnipparw ,uoy sguh eH
yenom erom dneps ot elpoep erom gnirb dna emoc lliw srac erom os ngiapmac da wen a rof saedi
.siht ot yas nac uoy gnihton s’erehT
,ereh yppah s’eh fi rednow uoY
,yromem a si siht taht enigami ot drah ton s’tI
,adoC yb ”namreH“ saw sihT
.sgoH erom on erew ereht
,og ,uoy segdun erutaerc ehT
,niaga pu kcab dna
.gniriw sih ot kcab seog dna shgis eH
.yrotsih ruoy ro namreH wonk meht fo enoN
,tnemom a rof tsuj ,niaga efas leef uoY .pu uoy sparw ,uoy ecaf ot snrut eH .kcab sih dnuora mih guh ,pu hsur uoY
.detlit skool esle gnihtyreve tub
?mih gnisahc uoy era yhw nehT“
,sgoH eht tuoba nrael uoY
.etarepsed dna diputs dnuos t’nseod taht rewsna on ,tsael ta ,rewsna on evah uoY ”  . . . tsuj I ,oN“
.namhserf a sa neve knud dluoc
.yaddim ot resolc s’ti hguoht ,tesnus s’ti ekil leef ti sekam thgil egnaro ,talf ehT
.esraoh ,syas eh ”,did I esruoc fO“
”?namreH pots ot yrt ot ereh uoy erA“
.lausu sa ,eludehcs dniheb er’uoY
”.lla ta toN .netfo yrev toN“
dna llat ylenecsbo s’eH .deyats eh dna
.seye sih ni noitome eht ees
.elprup denrut sah retaw eht yltnecer tub
,esruoc fo ,truoc ot tnew rekcatta ehT
.moolb lluf ni era saelaza knip sih
.yldednimtnesba kcen sih no racs gnol eht sbur eH .evisave
.kniht uoy ?nehW .syas eh
.flesruoy pots t’nac uoy tub ,gnidnes terger ll’uoy wonk uoy gnihtemos ,maerd eht tuoba gnihtemoS
.rehto hcae rof sgnileef ruoy dessefnoc uoy emit tsrif eht saw tI .efas saw tI
,sdoow eht ni erew uoY
dna pis dna enilcer uoy rehtegoT
?ksa ot wonk reven uoy did yhW
.nwonk ev’I lla s’ti ,efil elohw yM“ .syas eh
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.drawkcab uoy skconk tI
.siht fo edis gnorw eht no er’uoy taht kniht ot meht tnaw t’nod uoY
ygoloib rieht tuoba gnihtemoS
,dnah ruoy esiar uoY
.retaw rewollahs eht setagivan eh sa ria eht skcilf nif lasrod sih ,sllaf eht sehcaer eh nehW
llams si esuoh ehT
a tsuJ ro niaR elpruP ti sI“
.llik ot drah si eaglA“
”?evah I kniht uoy od regnol hcum woH“
,regnuoy saw eh nehW
eveileb uoy ,tnemom siht nI
”,yako eb ll’eH“ ”?yako eb eh lliW“
,xis raey ni ,yllaniF
.snoegruts yot eht gnignarra ot kcab og dna elims yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,gnisserped dnuos dluow ”,reganaM snoitaleR cilbuP roineS olleH“ tub
.egnaro llits si nus eht dna
.yeksihw eht s’ti ebyaM
.M.A 4 ta tnes uoy egassem eht htiw detnorfnoc er’uoy tub
.noynac eht seiduts eH
.stoor rieht htiw ti brosba saelaza ytsriht ehT
”,ekal siht si wonk I llA“
”.esle erehwemos og ot evah ll’eH
.yawyna kconk uoY
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tsrif ta eciton elpoep woh si sihT .redneval
?mih pots ot gniyrt uoy erA
.suolaej uoy ekam ot hguone esolc
.doohdlihc ecnis tlef t’nevah uoy niap gnilgnit
.edarg dnoces ni tem namreH dna uoY
.nosinu ni yas yeht ”,olleh ,hO“
.ereht t’nsi kcurt sih tub
.muirauqa ’skcoL eht rof noegruts lanoisseforp a sa dekrow eh
.sedecer ti sa ekal eht fo egde eht swollof dworc suoyoj ehT
,koolrevo eht ot klaw ,rac ruoy fo tuo teg uoY
;gnorw erew sniwT ehT
.ti tsniaga sevlesmeht werht yehT .llaw etercnoc suomrone na deretnuocne yeht ,raey hcaE
.revir eht ot ssarg yrd eht hguorht liart eht nwod mih wollof dna
yeksihw ruoy hsinif uoy oS .selims eH
,nosaes eht ni etal s’ti hguoht nevE
ti taht uoy ot raelc ylneddus s’ti tuB
.pots t’nod uoy tub ,yas uoy ”,lliw I“ .syas eh
.tsrif ta tnedicca no ,dehsurb smra ruoY
.sremmilg retaw eht ,ti dnuora llA
.yeksihw sih spis dna siht ta selkcuhc eH
,dimuh s’tI .dnuorgkcab eht ni raor senibrut ehT
.tnereffid era uoy ,uoy dnA
.gnihtyreve revo rednaw nus eht tel
,skcoL eht ot tuo evird uoY
”?pleh ot tnaw uoy diD
.neeb evah dluoc ew tahw eb s’teL
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,tuo teg dluoc gnihton taht tub
,ti tuoba teewt uoy fi ebyaM
.emoh evird eht no revo sdrow sih nrut uoY
.tiaw uoY .shgis eH
.raelc si esoprup siH
”.taht ekil detartnecnoc s’ti fI
.ffo srepat niar eht ,yllautnevE
”,repeeketaG olleH“ ,yas uoY
,seye kcalb elttil esoht ni
”.yhtlaeh dnuos t’nseod tahT“ ”.ti ekil fo dnik I
.syas yllanif eh ”,mad eht s’tI“
,spukcuf era esohw dna seigidorp era sdik esohw
.esuoh sih ot yek ehT .nwod kool uoY
.seirreb tseteews ,tsepir eht kculp dna esuap htob uoy ,setunim wef a rof dna ,liart eht gniworgrevo si hsub yrrebkcalb A
,llac ot ylrae oot ,ylrae ekaw uoY
.smaerd fo roloc eht si taht ytic eht ,ytic ruoy
.srae ruoy gulp uoy dna ,uoy stih ti erofeb gnimoc evaw kcohs eht ees uoY
”,yromem a ekil sleef tI“
,ytic eht rof tfel uoy tub ,nwot llams emas eht ni pu werg uoY
.ereh morf snoitcaer rieht tuo ekam t’nac uoy tub
.won ytpme si tol gnikrap ehT
s’erehT .emoh ton s’eh ;edisni krad s’tI
.niaga sezzub enohp ruoy ,woN
,gnitniop er’yehT
,decrovid nettog s’ohw :nwot ruoy fo no-sgniog eht no pu hctac uoY
yawa shguols ssenilenol fo doirep gnol ruoY
.mad eht tuoba elcitra aidepikiW eht tub ,mad lautca
.swollof noitseuq ’sniwT eht dna ,rac ruoy ot tuo goj uoY
.ymotana lanretni woc tuoba erom nrael ot enohp ruoy no eton a ekam uoY
tnaillirb a ton s’tI
.gniriw detacilpmoc fo lluf xob a revo dehcnuh mih dnif uoY
,revir egral a yb detcesib ytic a ni evil ot
.won evisnefed leef uoY
,muinaru tneps htiw edam senibrut eht
.deyonna gnitteg s’eH
,uoy dnuora lla pu gniworg ytiC kroY weN fo dnik a enigami uoY
.uoy ekil tsuj ,edixoid nobrac selahxe rac ruoY
.retaw eht skoolrevo taht kced a sah namreH .sey ,yas uoY
”.enoz tsalb eht fo tuo saw enoyreve erus ekam ot detnaw eH
.oot era snoitca rieht
.hself nettor ekil
mih dlot dna edam htob d’uoy ekal elttil eht ta tuo dekool uoY
.gnivaw-flah ,ylevitatnet
.boj ruoy esol d’uoy neht tuB“
.seton ruoy kcehc uoY
.oot eulb si revir eht dna ,eulb llits si yks eht dna ,enog era sracs dna ylleb sih dna
.dedne dlrow eht elihw rehto hcae dleh dna
”.reveN ?gnippid ynnikS“ .sksa eh
”.tsrif yeksihw ym hsinif em teL“
.retnec rotisiv eht fo wodniw eht ni sgnah ngis desolc A
knurd nettog ,deyats evah dluow uoy ebyam ,esrow erew sgniht fI
.noisolpxe gib a s’ti
”?uoy rehtob eagla eht seoD ?ekal eht ni miws ot ekil llits uoy oD“
.gnikniht s’eh tahw si yllaer ti ebyam dnA
,gnignits llits era sdnah ruoy
”,txet a uoy tnes I“
.esruoc egnahc ot uoy rof hguone eb dluow ti ebyam ,sisirc laer a erew siht fi taht s’tI
.egaugnal ydob sih no
ydob ruoy ta nwod kool uoY
.kcab sezeeuqs eh dna ,dnah sih ezeeuqs uoY
elbaeciton yldrah s’ti ,tcaf ni—elprup
.dog tnelovelam a fo eye eht ekil uoy sehctaw nus eht dna
.meht rof si ti ysae woh ees uoY .gnihgual
.wonk uoy hsif emos ,yllaniF
.detekcoryks tekram etatse laer eht erofeb emoh a esahcrup dna
.elbuort gib ni eb ll’eH
,llud saw krow ehT
.truh evah tsum sehsals esoht woh enigami nac uoy tub ,derujni ylevarg t’nsaw eh ,msilobatem wols a dna niks kciht gnivaH
.dnalni sdoog gnitropsnart ,revir eht fo edis raf eht no yb gniog si niart A
,rood eht snepo eh nehW
.enog er’yeht tub ,hctaw ot yats thgim sniwT eht thguoht uoY
.gnicnad llits era nomlas eht dna
noynac eht pu wolf ot gnitrats si ezeerb mraw a dna ,pu gnitaeh si yad ehT .tcaer t’nseod eH
.revaw t’nseod eH
,si yllaer ti naht resolc sdnuos nroh stI
.elgnim dna ,edart ,hsif ot ereh degrevnoc secalp ynam os morf elpoep ynam os esuaceb—syas elcitra eht ”,tseW eht fo teertS llaW eht“—
.won ffo desolc s’eH
.edisni sklaw dna yltpurba sdnats eH
.oga sraey esoht lla decalpsid erew ohw elpoep eht rof detaerc saw taht eno eht ,detacol si nwot wen eht erehw llih eht no derehtag sah dworc A
,tsehc ruoy ot setargim dnah ruoy nehT
.niks ruoy no selgnit eagla ehT
.YADOT RUASONID GNIVIL A TEEM
”.yad elgnis a toN
,ylthgit enohp ruoy hctulc uoY
.trapa meht llet ot elba neeb reven ev’uoY
.swoc ybab eht gnitruh s’ti fi rednow I“
,dewolla si gnihsif noegrutS
.tcatnoc eye ekam ot tey s’eh ,emit elohw sihT .eugnot sih htiw
.etercnoc eht ni gnihtemos s’ereht ebyam ro
.hsif tnaig fo serutplucs derehtaew tsap
sllaf eht nwod miws
”?neht ti od ot gniog s’eh ,oS“
;namreH ees ot enog evah dluohs reven uoY
.enog eb lliw namreH tub
.latnemgduj oot erew uoy taht uoy dlot syawla eH
.thgil eht ni elkraps dna retaw eht morf pael yehT .llaf dna esir seidob yrevlis ,kcihT
.uoy tuoba erac I wonk uoY . . . tsuj I ,yrroS“
.thgir s’tahw od ot nesohc yllanif d’uoy gniwonk fo ssenippah ysae eht
.ecnalab ffo uoy nworht s’ti
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.kool ot ecalp rehto eno ylno
revir eht kcab sdloh taht llaw etercnoc devruc eht ta tuo daetsni tub siht syas eh sa uoy ta kool t’nseod eH
.lariv og yllanif ll’uoy
,aes ta sraey evif tneps yeht ,nomlas tsom ekiL .revir ruoy pu raf maws ecno taht nomlas eguh
.lwoh sneris ,ecnatsid eht nI
,ytic lufituaeb siht ni
.deltnamsid ylisae os ton er’yeht ;aitreni fo dnik a evah serutcurts egral tub
.rohcirtep dna ,retaw gnilgrug
.denrael d’eh tahw ylppa ot deticxe saw eh dna
”.esruoc fo mad eht gnivomeR“
.ti od dluoc eH .ssecca eht sah eH .enoyna naht retteb mad eht fo erutcurts lanretni eht swonk eH .mih osla
.trofmoc railimaf ,dlo na si pirg hguor siH
.timil ezis lagel eht revo raf saw namreH dna ,esnecil gnihsif a evah t’ndid eh tub ,lla retfa
”.noisolpxe gib yrev a eb t’now tI
?ti noitseuq lliw ohw dna ,dnatsrednu uoy ,mad eht dliuber ll’yehT
.ecnerefer ecnirP eht teg lliw uoy naht regnuoy enoyna fi rednow uoY
,emas eht eb lliw gnihtyrevE
.yadnuS s’ti taht dnim reveN
.sruoy htiw dnah sih dnif uoY .emas eht od uoY
.esle erehwyna enoyna ot gnihton naem taht sladnacs lausu eht lla
.dlrow eht ta tuo ylknalb erats yehT
.wohs tnemtnioppasid ruoy tel ot ton yrt uoY
.txet yggorg a mih dnes uoy os
.rof edam erew yeht tahw si sihT
?tuoba uoy dlot reven eh taht morf ffo tuc neeb eh sah tahW
”.oot uoy evol llits I“
elttob retaw a pu llif uoY .syek ,tellaw ,enohp :stekcop ruoy leef uoY .retsaf ,retsaf ,no uoy sreehc hcamots ruoy ni erutaerc ehT
,shtap devap eht klaw uoy sa uoy ot tuo hcaer yehT
.eerf ylrettu gnileef dna retaw eht ni htob er’uoy noos tub ,tsrif ta suoicsnoc-fles ,hcnuh uoy dna ,sehtolc ruoy fo tuo pirts uoY
,sterger sah eh fi
,ereht ees d’uoy tahw rednow uoY
.seciov dna seirots dna sevil tnereffid esoht lla
.emoh tnerruc eht decart ev’uoy won dna
.dnah sih tsuj naht erom serolpxe dnah ruoY
.srood ssalg gnidils eht ni reep ,kcab dnuora kced eht wollof dna gniliar eht revo bmilc uoY .gnihtoN
.uoy evigrof ot mih tcepxe t’nod uoY .mih tfel uoY
.retaw eht morf gnisir kcab ylacs ,suomrone nA
.ti pleh t’ndluoc uoy tub ,suoivbo eb dluow tisiv ruoy rof nosaer eht ,ti dias uoy sa noos sa taht wenk uoY
.kcuts emoceb s’eh taht ,tnemom elbirroh a rof ,kniht uoy dna ,semit wef a sehsarht liat siH
”?edun eht ni gnimmiws neeb reve uoy
.sretaw gnisir eht ni degrembus saw hcihw ,egalliv rieht rof thguof ohw elpoep ehT
.fo elbapac er’yeht tahw erusnu er’uoY ”?wonk uoy od woH“
.seirreb depahs-lleb ,elprup rieht tae ot uoy rof etarepsed tsomla
.si ti ecin woh dna kcab si elprup eht woh
”?gnidne na ekil leef siht seoD“ .ksa uoy
.su llet ot yb deppots eH“ .hgual yehT
,muirauqa eht ta noonretfa enO
”,egnahc ot gniog si gnihtyreve nehw wonk reven uoY“
.kcurt der elttil sih ot txen krap uoY
aciremA htroN fo lla ni sdnuorg gnihsif tseb eht spahrep erew hcihw ,sllaf eht tuoba nrael uoY
.niaga ehtaerb nac sesuoh denword ,dlo ehT
.esac ni tsuj ,rab alonarg a barg dna
,gnippan saw namreH elihw
”.revir eht pu emoc ot elba eb t’ndluow spihs dnA
.teef dloc teg dna
yademos ,emitnaem eht ni raelc snur retaw eht fI
.nosaes ekoms gnirud lla ta edistuo og elpoep ynam ton dna
.gnileef railucep a s’tI“
.enif 002$ a htiw yawa deklaw nam eht
”,emit gnol a evil noegrutS“ ”.yakO“
.weiveR seitinamuH nrehtuoS eht ni deraeppa tsrif hcihw ,adoC yb ”namreH“
.uoy edisni ekal a saw ereht ekil tlef ti taht
,txet-ot-eciov gnisu liame na esopmoc ot nigeb uoY
.reganeet a sa ylisae os dnuof uoy evol eht detnarg rof koot uoY
.mih dekcatta dna efink gnidlof egral a htiw knat sih otni depmuj enoemos
?ti t’nsaw ,ytterp saw tI .elprup taht ,ti dessim yeht taht yas neve thgim elpoeP
.detcepxenu ton tub lufniap gnihtemos ta gnihctulc
evaH“ .tresed hgih eht otni dna
,serutcurts lanretni sti morf retaw eht otni gnihcael slacimehc enigami uoY
.llaw yarg elap ,htooms yltcefrep a si
,sdnah rieht esiar
.niht dna hgih si ekoms eht dna ,yadot toh oot ton s’tI
ekoms eht dna swodniw dehsams eht dna stsetorp eht tegrof pleh ot yrots ykriuq a ,kniht uoy
.kniht uoy ,trilf drawkwa na hcus s’eH
.yawa uoy wolb dluoc dniw fo tsug tsethgils eht ekil
.hcae ni ebuc eci erauqs ,egral a
”?gnidne si dlrow eht kniht uoy oD“
?uoy llet ot gniyrt eh saW
.niar eht semoc nehT
,ni gniruop neeb dah sgniht ,efil elohw ruoy rof tahT
.detnarg rof gnihtyna ekat t’ndluohs uoY“ .syas eh
.sdnuorg gninwaps rieht ot kcab yenruoj gnol eht rof pu gninettaf
,devivrus namreH ecniS
.nomlas eht rof thguof ohw elpoep eht tuoba nrael uoY
.pihsralohcs a no nwot siht fo tuo nettog evah dluoc eh ebyam ,yalp mih tel d’yeht fI
dna uoy drawot ssalg sih stlit eH
.revir eht degnahc mad ehT
”?ytic eht ni taht od uoy nac netfo woH
,duolc a ekil leef uoY
kcab gniylf ,ffo er’uoy nehT
”.tuo emoc ot evah lliw mad ehT“
klim rieht gninrut
,segdurg yna sdloh eh fi ro
”,mad eht dniheb ekal eht ni gniworg eagla wen a s’erehT“
,mad eht drawot ezag sih wollof uoY ”?swonk ohW“
?woH ?yhW ?erehW .og ,og
seog mad eht nehW
.sseltniop dna etirt os tlef lla ti ;traeh eht evah t’ndid uoy ,etunim tsal eht tA
,reeb ruoy hguorht yawflah er’uoy nehW
,won ylraelc skaeps eH .eman ot gib oot gnihtemos ,reggib raf
.sgniht retteb dna reggib rof denitsed erew uoy erus erew uoY
,siht fo lla wenk ydaerla eh fi tuo dnif ot
,tsrif ta thgiL .niar elpruP
kcilc evitamriffa na sekam
erus ton er’uoy ,duc fo gniwehc eht ro shcamots ruof eht—
.gurhs yehT ”?regnol hcum woH“
.yticirtcele s’ytic ruoy fo retrauq a tuoba setareneg dna
.setapissid rednuht ehT
.deliaf lla yeht tub ,mad eht pu wolb ot stpmetta lareves erew erehT
,gnuoy llits htob er’uoy taht
,peelsa erew uoy nehw tlef uoy tahw tegrof ot yrt uoY
;lacitnedi era taht secaf rieht no setucs fo snrettap eht tsuj ton s’tI
.snrut dna nid eht revo spetstoof ruoy sraeh eh ,wohemoS
,dias eh tahw rebmemer uoY
;nomlas eht tsuj t’nsaw tI
.ssob ruoy morf noitacifiton a htiw sezzub enohp ruoY
.lacisum ton tub hgih era seciov riehT
”?semiT eht ’o ngiS
revir eht htiw no gniog yllaer s’tahw wonk lliw namreH
.tey erus ton er’uoY .degnahc sah gnihtemos rO
”.yademos niaga uoy ees ll’I ebyaM“ .syas eh
,yaw eno sexelf liat siH
.nigeb ot erehw wonk t’ndluow uoY .gniht a hcus od reven dluow uoY .mad eht pu wolb ot tnaw uoy esuaceb toN
.noitseuq eht fo tuo mees ton seod erutuf eht gnieeS
.maeb elgnis a ni yks eht otni pu seog retaw eht ,sneppah ti nehW
.retal ,won ton tuB
.riaf eb t’ndluow tsuj ti ;nosaer siht rof maet llabteksab s’loohcs ruoy morf derrab saw eH
,uoy morf yawa snrut eH ”?yhw nehT“
.reivaeh dna reivaeh neht
”.ereh tuo ylenol eb tsum tI
.sboj remmus gnikrow sreganeet lla ,secaf railimafnu fo lluf era sknat noegruts ehT
.yawa uoy sehsup eh litnu
.ezag sih ni llams leef uoY
”.mih pots ot gniyrt t’nsaw I“
.eid ot stnaw eh taht ton s’tI .snaem eh tahw dnatsrednu uoY
eht tub ,lla ta uoy egdelwonkca ,eyb-doog yas
,ti tuoba etirw ll’uoy ebyaM
gnihtemos ta tub uoy ta toN .egaR
,pleh yeht dna ,sesicrexe gnihtaerb ruoy od uoY
.egap muideM sih no
,tsae—yawhgih eht pu
.sdaer gnidaehbus a ”,tcilfnoC“
.retnec rotisiv eht kcehc uoY
.sesuoh eht gnoma ecnad dna
.won ecalp eht nur yeht ekil skooL
.kcab emoc ll’ti ,tnaw uoy lla ti nosioP
.syas eh ”,wonk I“ .yas uoy
.denruter nomlas esoht ,sraey evif rof
,war a leef dna ,smlap ruoy niks ,flesruoy hctac uoY
.mih eb dluow ti ,mad eht pu wolb ot tnaw dluow enoyna fI
.fo tros ,tcejbus eht egnahc ot yrt uoY
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”?morf emoc ti did erehW“ ”.wonk t’nod I“
,esuoh s’namreH fo tnorf ni pu llup uoY   .skcoL eht ot
.hcaeb eht no pu dne uoY
.hguone raelc s’ti tub ,ylthgils tsuj
.yvaeh os tlef uoy taht
,nwod dna pu thgiarts er’uoY
.seye ruoy epiw uoY
.llew ot trats sraet eht leef uoY
,roloc eht setartnecnoc—
”?ereh llits er’uoy tuB“
.noitom wols ni selbmurc llaw ehT
.moor eht ssorca ti lruh ot egru eht thgif
.skool ti yaw eht sekil eh ebyam tub ,recin gnihtemos droffa dluoc eH
.egnaro nus eht dna yarg yks eht snrut taht
.enog eb lliw namreH dnA
tub nibac gol a etiuq ton ,citsur dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,stibihxe roodtuo dlo eht hguorht klaw uoY
.revir eht ot seert elpam wolley ,gnirehtiw eht revo tuo kool
,sretaw repeed otni tuo
.mlac eht odnu ylkciuq dna enohp ruoy kcehc ylevixelfer uoY .elttil a
.trapa tfird uoy ;og stel eH
.tsiruot a ekil evird ot gnidneterp ,ylwols muirauqa ’skcoL eht ot pu esiurc uoY
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
.egilbo uoy tub ,etirovaf ruoy ton er’yehT
”,ti fo erac doog ekaT“
,tliub saw mad eht retfA
”.kcab revir eht egnahc ot si eagla eht fo dir teg ot yaw ylnO
:enohp ruoy rof eton rehtonA
.skcor gnikcats ,sgorf gnihctac ,sdik elttil erew uoy nehw tol a enod d’uoy gnihtemos saw tI
,sessalc gnireenigne gnikat saw eh tub ,won ti rof dlo oot erew uoY
.yawa evird ruoh-owt a tsuj ,ereh eb syawla d’eh thguoht uoY
.egnahc ot gniog si gnihtyreve nehw wonk reven uoY
kcab sih no gnitaolf s’eH
. . . rednow reve uoy t’noD“
”.os sraeppa ti ,seY“
,retaw eht syas royam ehT
,yeksihw fo sessalg owt htiw snruter eh nooS
.oot suomordana era noegruts
.sllig eht sbmun fo tros tI
.tey emit emos evah eW“
.ylleb a fo tib a depoleved s’eh eciton uoy
.selbmum eh ”,saw ti hsiw I“
.llawyap a dniheb dekcol si elcitra eht tub
,ekoms htiw yarg llits si yks ehT
.muirauqa eht ot kcab rotom uoY
.ylbmud ,ereht dnats uoY
,namreH txet ot tnaw uoY .tsixe t’ndluohs
,hsif a ton er’uoY
”namreH“   yojne esaelP
.sllig sih revo sehsaw retaw ehT
.tbuod on ,thguac eb ot ton gnipoh dna enohp rieht nO
,ni kcab pmuj yeht ,erehT
”?retlif retaw a teg dluohs I kniht uoy oD“
revir eht yb seirrebkcalb dekcip dna
.kniht uoy ,raf oS
.retaw eht fo tuo flah gnihcuorc ,kcab eht ni eno ees uoY
.ydaets si liat sih fo gnitaeb
,sevael elpam yb neddih
”?lufmrah ti sI“ .snialpxe eh
.flesruoy ot sgnisum eseht peek dluohs uoy wonk uoy tub
.desolc seye sih htiw
.pu lla ti knard dna tsae eht morf emac doolf eht ,7591 ni yad eno no tub ,sraey fo sdnasuoht rof ereht devil dah yehT
.niaga eerf dewolf retaw ehT
.retaw eht revo ylisae gnivom dnuos eht
,hsif rehto wef a htiw knat ykcum ,yarg a ni devil eH
.retaw eht tuoba ksa uoy
,woh wonk dluow enoyna fi dnA
.eagla rof ecalp doog a ti edaM
”.yldaed erew ti hsiw I“
”.mih retfa og t’ndluohs uoY“
.royam eht tsurt t’nod uoy tub ,knird ot efas llits era ,klim eht dna
.reeb dloc a uoy sreffo dna
.syas eh tahw ton s’ti tuB
.namreH dekcatta d’eh yhw nialpxe t’ndluoc tub
.noislupmoc sseldnim a saw tI
,htrof dna kcab gnisiurc
.sllaw eht no worg nehcil dna ssom ,secalp ni dna
:eurt si ”suomordana“ dna
.yas ot mih tnaw uoy ,nwot ruo ot kcab emoC
.erutuf eht ni raf s’taht tuB
.yleritne sraeppasid eh erehw
.skcoL eht fo repeeketaG eht s’eh esuaceb dna noegruts a s’eh esuaceb
”?tahw gniod morf mih potS“
.gniliar radec eht tsniaga nael dna
,rac ruoy ot tuo tfird uoY
.gnigreme si egalliv dlo ehT
.mlap ruoy otni drah dna dloc gnihtemos sesserp
,sksa yldlob repapswen s’etats ruoy
.rehtegot ,kcor yb kcor ,nwod mad eht dekcik uoY .deddon eH
.llew meht htiw gnola tog namreH tub ,gnilttesnu siht dnuof syawla ev’uoY .citobor tsomlA
”.suomordanA olleH“ ,snirg eh dna
yllanoitnetni gnieb s’eh taht tnih emos kees uoY
,noisiv larehpirep ruoy ni sniamer sucof ruoy tub
,thgirb dna yrevlis sgniht rof revirnwod detnuh uoY
ykcul flesruoy deredisnoc syawla ev’uoY   adoC yb
.ereh ti evol uoy yhw rebmemer uoY .seugnot dna sregnif ruoy niats uoY
.smaerd fo roloc eht ,ytic ruo tisiV
”.elprup s’ti fi nevE
.romalc eht raeh tsomla nac uoY
,niaga drawrof gnidilg s’eh neht tuB
,ytic ruoy rof tniop gnilles a eb dluoc roloc eht ebyaM
.dedworc ton s’tI
emit fo doirep trohs ylevitaler a ni yenom fo tol a evas ot elba saw eh tnaem gnisuoh eerf eht tub
.efil laer ni naht retfos hcum os ,tfos si dnas ehT
,dnah ruoy sbarg eH
,ylerus ,su fo ynaM
?gnihtemos gnittolp ydaerla eh saW . . .
eht toN .mad ehT
.rellat reve gniworg era sehsub lalas eht tub ,tey nwod nekat neeb t’nevah dna sugnuf fo deid lla evah seert radec ehT
,syad eseht noegruts ees ot tnaw elpoep ynam toN
.noitom ni uoy stes ,evohs eltneg a htiw dna uoy snips eh nehT
.loop gnimmiws a ekil ,mraw s’tI
.mad eht fo sniamer nekorb eht sehcaer ti erehw llafretaw a gnitaerc ,deb ekal eht fo mottob eht ta gnimrof si lennahc wen A
.gnignahc si gnihtemoS
”.ereh fo tuo teg ot setunim wef a evah ylno ll’uoy ,ffo siht tes I nehW .oG“
.nus eht ni denetsilg seidob riehT
.sesnet dnah siH .ssefnoc uoy
.drawpu ylthgils gnilruc slebrab rieht ,elims emas eht elims yehT
.flehs a no snoegruts deffuts hsulp gnignarraer era ,srekrowoc dlo s’namreH fo elpuoc a ,sniwT ehT
.hguoht ,drawretfa yats ot elba eb t’now eH“ .elims yeht
.ekal eht ot nwod mih wollof uoY
.looc ti yalp ot yrt uoY
”?evael ot tnaw reve uoy t’ndiD
”,yawa hsaw ll’I ,seog mad eht nehW“
”.wonk ew lla s’tahT .elihw elttil A“
:esimorp s’ngis daor dedaf a yb yawhgih eht ffo derul tsiruot detnioppasid lanoisacco eht htiw seifles rof gnisop
.tca ot deen uoY .ekil sleef ti tahw s’taht
.gnivael mih fo thguoht eht dnats t’nac uoY
.tuhs rood eht raeh yldrah ,edisni teg
.hsilprup ti dnif dna
.kcab gniog er’uoy ;gnitxet htiw lleh oT
,pu pmuj yeht ,hguone wollahs si retaw eht nehW .sgoH ehT
,pu kool ll’eh fi rednow uoY
”.emoclew er’uoY“ ”.uoy knahT“
.nepo ediw rood ytiruces-hgih eht tfel eh ;ni mih wollof ot ysae s’tI
.erom gnihtyna ees ot gnideen tuohtiw mih s’ti wonk uoY
.esuoh ruoy dniheb keerc eht ni mad a gnidliub erew uoY .neetfif ro neetruof htob erew uoy nehw tnemom a llacer uoY
yllanif uoy dna ,uoy ot kcab snrut eH
,kcab ruoy no taolf nac uoY .ecin sleef tI“
.uoy ees ot desirprus kool t’nseod eH
.mih fo tuo erom gnihtyna teg nac uoy fi erus ton er’uoY .dorp uoy
mad eht ,ecnatsid siht tA
”?tuo emoc ot evah mad eht lliw yhW“
.ruopnwod eht hguorht reep dna pu flesruoy tfil uoY
,tnemom siht ni ,woN
.erew ew ekil eb s’teL .em htiw eviL
.niaga elprup eb lliw ti
.yltcerid uoy ta dekool reve eh fi
.lennahc eht ni esle gnihtemos s’erehT
.sdrow eht rof gnihcraes ,etatiseh uoY