.niap htiw depley ruatonim depparwne-teknalb eht dna ,liat sih fo esab eht rof thgir gnimia
.elttek eht dellif I nehw maerts eht fo tuo yot ybab ruoy koot I ,netsiL"
,sredluohs dna kcen sih hcterts dna pu tis ot etipser eht fo egatnavda koot setseluK ,troter a kcab gnitiB
.der krad a ot gninedder tlep nworb sih htaeneb niks sih
,htolcniol nelloow deruoloc ylthgirb a dna snroh rof skcits devrac owt htiw ,llod llub nelloow llams A
deganam dah ypmurG ,esruoc fO
.lluks sih ot denettalf srae sih
.kcap eht fo mottob eht ta gniht tsal eht tuo dellup eh sa denediw reens s'ypmurG
ekil mees seseluM sdrawot edutitta s'ypmurG edam taht yaw a ni evisolpxe dna derepmet-lli
,tnelis dna dellappa ,setseluK
.sussateM yb ”pihsroW oreH“
setseluK .ti tae t'ndluoc tub
.ecalp lufwa siht ni
,ssensuoicsnoc sih gnithgif
eht fo trap sa kcab emit emos gnitirw detrats sussateM
"?kniht uoy'd ,dab oot ton s'taht ,llew
,mitciv wen sih otni dehcnual ypmurG  .deedni ,gnibbolS
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb uoy rof daer si yrots s’yadoT
,dna semit lla ta ruof denwo rehtaf siH
”pihsroW oreH“ saw sihT
.reilrae sraey evif
evres ot emoh sih morf yawa tnes gnieb ta ssensuovren dna
.denruter—edirp fo erusaem a dna—feileR
.rehtegot sdroc eht deit dna no ti tup eh ,yltfeD
,redael eht morf tnemmoc gnibij eht emac
raey fo emit siht rof erutarepmet lausu eht saw ria ehT
"?gnikooc ym ekil uoy t'noD .tae woN
.koorb eht otni yot ybab eht delruh redael eht nehw ,raf oot enog dah siht gnikniht
.dnats larutan a ekil dekool niaga ti os yawa lairetam dellef eht deraelc dna
.tiab eht ot esor reven dna erofeb lla meht draeh dah ruatonim der ehT
setunim evif txen eht ni steknalb yttihs ruoy gnihsaw hsinif t'nod uoy fI"
,denosaer eh ,ylbaborP
,hguorht mih demraw esicrexe ehT
",syot ybab htiw yalp t'nod stpircsnoC"
ruonoh sih tuoba denrecnoc erom s'eh—
,dum htiw deyortsed saw htolcniol eraps siH
.em rof ni ti tup 'ah tsum rehtom-m yM
"!reets-trac RUO eb lliw UOY ro
.moc.sussatem no ro
.reh dniheb si liat esohw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,taht dekcinap dna tespu os saw seseluM ,won yB
.meht htiw dellif lortap a ni rotnemrot rehtona
,laedi eb dluow ralucitrap ni enO
.em ot ti evag rehtom ym dna
".ti tuoba dehgual lla yeht ,yad gniwollof ehT
.tcepxe ot tahw mih gnillet
,saw eh taht hbraT fo redael elbon taerg eht ,ypmurG
.kcap ym ni efas s'tI
.llub yrros dna das eht ediseb tas dna revo lwob nwo sih thguorb eH
,nossetnegrA setnorB fo nos eht naht ynapmoc gniniatretne erom raf meht dnif ot demees ypmurG
,niaga pmac edam lortap eht erofeb yrd eb dluow yeht yaw on saw ereht dna
si yrots s’yadoT
,llordeb sih dellor ,noitom yreve ni nettirw yresim
,sehcnarb eht deppirts ,ti dellef eh
"?ko ,pu nethgil ,seseluM"
,kcik elgnis a htiW
.reets-trac a sa syad ruoy evil dna deredner eb annaw uoy sselnu
.serif owt dees ot repmet sih ni hguone gnitaerc ,rednit eht no tuo regna sih koot
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy
"!yot ybab a tsuj ,'nihton s'tI
dna evitatnemugra ,ylrus saw setmmurG
meht fo 563 evah ll'eh tniop emos tA
.naps-dnah a dedda ylerem snroh derepat dna devruc yltneg sih
.eugnot cibreca sih htiw htuoy eht morf spirts gnippir ylirrem
.redluob a ekil ylbakramer dekool won llordeb sih
.kcab erab sih no tpircsnoc regnuoy eht deppals setseluK
.doow emos teg ot ffo devom dna
,retawniar fo loop llams a ni steknalb sih gnihsaw saw seseluM .doowerif fo daol sih htiw pmac eht ot denruter setseluK nehw emoclew a detnurg sroirraw redlo eht fo enO  .raef ni revihs mih edam taht taerht a
,sroirraw owt rehto eht fo tnemesuma eht ot hcum ,meht tuoba ylduol gnitnemmoc dna smeti gnitseretni gnivomer
.ecaf enivob sih ni trapa ediw tes erew seye nworb yldnik
seirots erom roF
.erad reven dluow eH"
.ytiniffA ruF no puorg "tpmorP yadsruhT"
.ti noitnem t'noD"
.evael ot hcir oot raf dna gnixaler
.trops s'redael rieht ta dewaffug seinorc s'ypmurG
.liob ot tevirt eht no ti decalp eh erofeb
".ti swonk eh dna si eh naht regnorts m'I
emoceb ot elam gnuoy eht desuac tluassa ehT
.'ecneitap' ro 'srennam'
,srecuas ekil seye sih
,llik ot saw eh gnieb eht detnecs dna dehcuot gnivaH
seot evif htiw teef ni dedne sgel lufrewop ,gnortS
.noitalsnart ni tsol tog ylbaborp elims sih taht desilaer setseluK dna ,pmil gnignah liat
.seye yretaw dna sdnah gnilbmert htiw
a dna kcab sih fo llams eht ta dehsup toof dniknu nA
,enizagam nocorhtnA eht ni deraeppa sah krow siH
:tpa oot lla aitilim eht nihtiw emankcin sih edam hcihw ,gnihtyna htiw yppah reven
.gnimaercs dna gnilwoh ,woleb dnuora delworp sedarmoc sih dna enola thgin lla ereht saw eH
,flesmih ot delims setseluK ,setnorB .aitilim hbraT eht ni efil fo ecneirepxe s'raey a ,neht yb ,dah rehtorb redle siH
,srehto eht fo thgis fo tuo
,tew dna dnuownu erew sllor gnidnib dnah sih
,ti rof refas erehwemos dnif dluohs uoy kniht I neht tub
.liob doolb 'setseluK edam tahT
.peels sih ni dettam dah ti erehw secalp eht ni talf eil ot tlep sih teg ot flesmih gnikahs
,nos dnoces sih htiw yrgna nehw
tsafkaerb hsinif I erofeb llordeb ruoy otni steknalb esoht teG"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.llordeb llams sih dekcap dah eh hcihw ni rennam eht revo tpircsnoc rehtona gnitegrat
.enod htrae no krow sih redisnoc dna
.sgnidlohdnal s'rehtaf sih dna
.dnuorg tfos eht otni meht gnidnirg
,ypmurG ta deralg setseluK
.dekil ylralucitrap setseluK mohw fo rehtien
".lanosrep gnihton s'tI .ti hguorht reffus lla eW .dezah gnieb er’uoY" .delims eh
sih dna ,lufthguoht dna mlac saw ecaf siH
.gnorts dna llat worg ot dedeen ti thgil eht ti teg ot gniog reven saw dnats eht fo elddim eht ni noitisop sti
.rewop dna htgnerts
,lamron yleritne dna ,lanoitidart saw gnizah dna tnemesabed siH
fo ecnaraeppa na mih evag tsehc delcsum llew dna daorb a pota sredluohs daorB
.deggurhs dna deffuh setseluK   .noitaroda fo lluf dna kcurtsewa
.thgin lla ,nezorf ro
.yoj erup fo maeb a otni denediw ecaf sih neht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dluoc eh sa steknalb sih fo tuo retaw hcum sa dezeeuqs tsrif gnivah
,ten.ytiniffaruf no yhpargotohp sih weiv dna sgnitirw sih daer nac uoY
,devirra eh erofeb ecivda 'setnorB dah eh tub
;tew steknalb ruoy teg uoy si sneppah taht lla fI"
.saw eh erehw deniamer eh ,tiderc sih ot
.eno eht tsuj htiw epoc ot evah su fo tser eht dna"
deraor eciov peed derepmet-dab
,nrow dna trohs slianregnif
,ria gninrom dloc eht ni gnivom ylision ,snoinapmoc gnikaw ruof sih morf esion eht
.tcaer t'ndid flac gnuoy ehT
,ecneitapmi htiw gnitrons ,yawa edorts ypmurG
.ris ,lufetarg m'I"
,erom daeh dna sredluohs sih derewol seseluM
.ysae kool boj eht gnikam htgnerts sih
,namsdoow desitcarp a fo lliks eht htiW
",htolcniol rehtona ,hhhO"
,kcap sih dniheb gnihtemos deppord eh ,denruter eh sA
,kcik rehtona setseluK evag eH .ypmurG
"!PU EPAHS nehT ?oN
rehtael deruoloc-nat thgil a saw erow eh htolcniol ehT
.eno detlep der eht ot daeh sih detfil ylwols seseluM
,xobrednit sih ot dednetta dna ylbidua dehgis setseluK
,ti retfa og ot devom dna rorroh ni depsag seseluM
dlihc a ton s'eH
sdnal yawa-raf egnarts ni snisuoc tnatsid fo seirots draeh dah setseluK .sevooh ton—
,snoinapmoc-dees sti htiw noititepmoc ni reveroF
,sraet ni won saw ohw ,retsgnuoy etanutrofnu eht fo noitilomed eht dehsinif ypmurG elihw
.snemiceps regral rehto xis fo ertnec eht ni saw ti sa
,kcap s'eno gnuoy eht fo stnetnoc eht hguorht degammur
.thginot ezeerf nac uoy dna maerts eht ni ereht dneirf elttil ruoy nioj ll'yeht
"!flac ,won esuoh gib ruoy ni moor enif a ni ton er'uoY
.gniyfirret saw dauqs sih denioj eh nehw gnizah sih taht em dlot rehtorb yM
elihw a rof gnitnap doots dna ksat eht fo dne eht yb ylivaeh gnitaews saw eH
.efil ,retteb ,rehtona evah dluow ti erehw
.kcap flow a yb dekcatta gnieb saw ti dedneterp dna llih a no mih denodnaba yehT
,derrits eh sa mra sih fo ruf eht otni ria mraw deffuh eH !nwad eht nmaD
.tnempmacne rieht ediseb koorb yddum eht otni meht dehcnual ypmurG
:airuaT ni erauqS taerG eht detanimod taht eutats eht ni setooB fo toof eht yb flac gnuoy eht ekil ecaf s’eno der eht otni dekool seseluM  ".ris ,uoy knahT"  "?KO ,ti retfa kool ll'I"  ".hO"
,dehgis setseluK
”pihsroW oreH“   yojne esaelP
,ruot siht hsinif ew litnu ereht ti evael nac uoY
.eno gnuoy eht rof ylpeed tlef
retaw eht otni niarg-liart fo kcas s’lortap eht fo emos deruop neht
!seitilibisnopser ylimaf sih dna
.desnednoc regnol on htaerb sih ,remraw werg yad eht sa dna
.eciov dloc a ni ypmurG dereens
,yellaV airuaT eht fo trap siht ni seert daed wef erew erehT
,ebut a gnilbmeser morf raf
noisufnoc fo sgnileef sih deyarteb seye gniknilb-tsaf esohw ,seseluM deman retsgnuoy detpircsnoc-ylhserf a
.retaw htiw ti llif ot nordluac nori kcalb eht htiw koorb eht ot ffo depmots neht ,erif eht revo dopirt gnidlof llams a devom eH
,denosaer eh ,emit eht lla seot-pit no gniklaw ekil eb dluow tI
.emoserit yrev eb dluow taht dna
.noops sih htiw lwob nedoow eht dnuora hsam tsafkaerb sih delriws eh sa seseluM ot yllairotaripsnoc derepsihw eh ,esolc gninaeL
,detanidroocnu erom neve
.gnivil eht gnoma morf mitciv sih tceles ylluferac ot dah ruatonim eht os
.aitilim eht fo tser eht ot kcab deredluohs-dnuor sih
derettum setseluK ,ecaf s'ypmurG no kool gums eht gnieeS
.tsaf mih gnidloh ,redluohs eht yb mih debbarg dnah s'ypmurG tub
,nrecnoc dna tnemssarrabme htiw delaeuqs eH
.ylkciuq tnemeticxe sih deliev ruatonim gnuoy eht os ,ylsuoicipsus mih dehctaw ,ybraen gnittis ,ypmurG
.tsol s'ti ,won dnA
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb uoy rof daer ,sussateM yb
.dnim sih morf gnidaf ydaerla erew taht serusaelp eht ot gninruter morf setseluK peek ot hguone saw
.reisae yna ti ekam t'ndid taht tub
.kcapkcab sih otni kcab snoissessop wef sih tup ot deirt eH
".setseluK ,decargsid ma I
taht naelc ot emit gnol a ekat dluow tI
,eert llams eht fo elob eht no snroh htob dna sdnah htob tup neht ,dnuorg eht no exa sih decalp setseluK
.meht hguorht thgir dekaos dah retaw maerts yllems dna kcum nworB .etal oot saw ti tub
.dap eson knip-lraep tfos sih no deralf slirtson sih ,ria psirc eht fo lufgnul peed a delahni eh sA
,ecnis ti dah evah ylimaf ym fo llA
.htuoy siht fo htped eht desilaer ylneddus setseluK .yrd tey ,der erew seye s'roirraw gnuoy ehT
,dnalerI fo tsew dliw eht ni desaB
ebut thgit llams a otni llordeb nwo sih dekcap yltrepxe dah eH
.lufniap saw ti dna
,pmad eb rehtie dluow seseluM roop tnaem hcihw
.flac etaciled a ot rehtom gnivol a fo taht
,peed saw maerd ehT  sussateM yb
",yot ybab taht denwo rehtafdnarg-taerg-taerg yM"
!yllaeR"  .noitcaer oN
.hgual a detrons setseluK  "?gab ruoy skcehc redael eht fi tahw tuB
,meht retfa delbmarcs seseluM
"?huH ?ylooM elttil rof siht kcap rehtom diD
.ruf hsidder krad sih htiw ylecin detsartnoc taht
.dneirf eno tsael ta htiw saw eh taht wonk mih tel ot ,elims yldneirf a mih dehsalf setseluK .tespu dna sseldneirf os dekool seseluM rooP
,suortxed dna etalucitra erew sdnah siH
,seseluM ,erif eht fo edis rehto eht nO
!pmul der yzal ay ,uoy nmaD !nossetnorB"
ti gnuh dah eh erehw morf htolcniol sih eveirter ot daeh sih evoba hcnarb eht ot pu dehcaer eh sa mutorcs sih dehctarcs eh ,yleguh gninwaY
emoh enif 'setseluK tuoba stnemmoc debrab ni dethgiled osla ypmurG ,neht tub
.tsixe dluoc gniht a hcus eveileb t'ndluoc eh tub
.ti yned t'ndluoc eH
elpoep sih fo ytied eht gniksa elihw lartsadA eht ot ecnesse s'efil sti gnigdelp
,naorg-flah-tnurg-flah a htiw esor eH
.tnaegres rieht morf saw eciov ehT
.reh dniheb si liat esohw
,yhtapme siht ,gniht suoicsnocbus a saw tI
,mih ta gnihgual saw ruatonim der eht thguoht evah tsum seseluM
,leef thgim reets-trac a denigami eh ekil ylbatrofmocnu leef mih edam ydob sih morf esir maets gnihctaW  .doog saw tahT
.steknalb sih ta yldas gnirats dna revo dehcnuh ylbaresim
... elttil A ?siht s'tahw dnA"
.ertnec eht otni revo dedlof stniop neetxis eht fo eno htiw ,epahs fo tuo tneb saw lartsadA sih neve
-- noitpo elttil saw ereht tuB
.mih tuoba gnorw neeb dah eH
.flac elttil eht rof yllod a s'tI !teews woh ,hO !yllod
,ecivres deretne eh nehw kcab bmud dna deracs sa tsuj dekool eh fi gnirednow
,teef rof sevooh nevolc dah ohw
;netfo mih redner ot denetaerht
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
.evorg tseraen eht ni srefinoc rellams eht dekcehc eh
.yas ot tahw wonk t'nod I -I .yllaeR
.seinorc sih ot detrons dna kcap eht morf htolcniol dnoces a tuo dellup ypmurG
.ekatsim yb retnirp sih no yllanoisacco dna ,4 .loV gnaF ni
.emit eht fo tsom ssenredliw eht ni gnivil eno morf detcepxe eb thgim sa
fo stra eltbus eht ot emac ti nehw nosrep luftcat tsom eht ton saw
.efil elohw sih ni taht sa deracs sa reven saw eh dias eH
... yot devol-llew a saw ylniatrec ti
,taht tA  "!ybab roop ,wA
,traeh yvaeh a htiW
?lobmys dercas eht egamad ylgnilliw enoyna dluoc woH
.seye sih morf peels s'gninrom eht depiw eh erofeb
.saw eh erehw niamer ot gnilggurts
.dlihc a saw eh nehw flesmih setooB yb ti nevig saw eH" .ylteiuq dias eh
,gnihtyreve yllautriv no dnats ot—yllarutan—
:deerb sih fo nemiceps enif a saw eH
."selaT droW 563" meht gnillac ,noitcif-orcim detimil-drow no neek ylralucitrap si eH
,dnuorg eht ta tsomla gnitniop snroh
,kool ot dnuora gnuws seseluM
,daeh sih ta llat sertem flah a dna owt tuoba
.redro eht tuo dewolleb eH
,tsif sih ni noops nedoow sih dleh tpircsnoc gnuoy ehT .seseluM rab—tsafkaerb rieht rof lufetarg erew sroirraw eht fo hcae dna ,gnimoclew saw doof eht fo llems ehT
,ffurg saw rehtorb gib siH
.sraey rof noitanicsaf deifirroh-imes htiw meht dehctaw gnivah
sgol depahs-ylmrofinu otni knurt eht pu deppohc
.hsam niarg toh fo lwob lluf a aitilim eht fo hcae devres setseluK
,deppord waj 'seseluM  "?kniht uoy
,flac ,tsorf eht ni sroodtuo gnipeels nuf on s'tI
.yot ybab a deedni saw bmuht dna regnif s'ypmurG neewteb dehcnip tcejbo ehT
,doof eht htiw deyalp
,htaerb sih rednu "dratsab"
.deerb I nehw flac tsedle nwo ym ot ti ssap ot elba eb ton lliw I
?huH ?flac ,tnaw uoy tahw tahT
,tub ,ssol dna truh fo ksam a otni detrotnoc ecaf s'retsgnuoy ehT
.mih looc dna ydob sih morf yawa kciw ot erutsiom eht wolla ot
.daerht deruoloc-gnorw htiw secalp ni dehctap ylluferac dna tcatnoc morf nrow
.emalf otni redluoms ot ssarg deird dna tnilf eht gnitteg
,edirts sih ni won saw ypmurG taht pleh t'ndid tI
"!erif tsafkaerb eht trats dna dnuorg eht ffo edih sselhtrow ruoy teG
kcap sih fo pot eht morf exa sih debbarg
,dees wen a ot tirips s'eert eht yevnoc ot
.yot ybab ym s'ti -I"
!dnuora gnibbols fo dnik siht rof emit evah t'nod ew uoy dlot I"
.thgin suoiverp eht
.rethgual htiw deraor srehto ehT