,yllacisyhp tsomla
tsacdop slebeR sraW ratS eht stsoh osla ohw ,rehtnap emit-lluf a
yggodikahk@ elppaenip yggodikahk@ ot tuo hcaer esaelp
,og krof sih tel ahcaS
.nwod tnew daeh s’ahcaS dna esor moM
,feiler fo hgis a tuo tel ahcaS ”.yllaicepse miH
”?siht tuoba mih ot klat ot rehtaf ruoy
.eye sih delcric taht ruf etihw fo hctap a gnibbur
.enevretni thgim rehtaf sih erofeb
.ffo nekat tey ton d’eh temleh eht fo tuo dekop srae yerg-hsiulb owT
.saw eh rekoj eht ekil tuo eht gnitpecca
,dednuorg saw eh ecnahc tnecrep ytenin a saw erehT
.reyof eht fo sroolf doowdrah eht otno gnispalloc draobetaks
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.drah gnar sbals tnemec s'yawevird eht revo gnillor sleehw cimarec fo kcarc drah A
si yrots s’yadoT
,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.elbat eht ta sevlow rehto owt eht gnitatirri ,tuoba dehctarcs latem ehT
.tsrif eiggeR ot klat ot evah I yhw ees t'nod I“
.elbat eht no drah nwod emac swap s’ahcaS
.elpmis taht t’nsaw tI
.teef owt no klaw dluoc ti
.seirrow sih fo emos ffo llup ot hguone noitceffa reh
”?gnihtemos ro tuo skaerf eh fi tahW
.ylralimis eciov reh deppord moM
,etalp sih dnuora sgge dloc dellor ahcaS etoyoC triD yb
,ekops eh sa sdrow sih delevarg dna
yleniuneg ot dah eH
.margelet ro rettiwt no
.mih no sesirprus yna gnignirps ekil t'nod eW
,wonk uoY" .dehguoc ehs dna
,roirp dnekeew ehT
,tluciffid gnihtyreve ekam ot dah eh
lla dna oga sraey deneppah tahT
,ekops daD ron moM rehtieN
.ahcaS sa deyonna sa tsuj
ytilauxes sih dnatsrednu rehtorb elttil sih pleh dna yrt
potelbat etinarg eht tsniaga derettalc slisnetu reH
,denepo rood tnorf ehT
.yrt did yllaer eh ,dog ho ,esuaC
mih llet tsuJ ?sedud etad I
.kcehc ni slworg esoht peek ot gninraw a ,detniuqs daD
sdrawpu gnihsalf
.snoitseuq evah ll’eH“
yrrufos no etoyoCtriD sa sgnitirw sih dniF
.tuo emoc d'ahcaS ecnis toN
,mih truh snoisserpxe rieht gnieeS
.ot rewsna eht wonk t’now I snoitseuQ
.htnom a neeb d'tI .eltbuS ".ylevol
.dniheb morf mih degguh ehs sa nwo sih tsniaga gnihsurb sreksihw ,sredluohs sih revo depard smrA
.edistuo morf mih raeh ot elba eb t'ndluow rehtorb elttil siH ".tsrif
,htaerb peed a koot
.sregnif sih neewteb krof sih gnilddiwt
?mih htiw klat owt uoy t’nod yhW"
,eciov sih gnirewol dna ni gninaeL
?yas ot em tnaw uoy od tahW“
”!dnatsrednu t’nod syug uoY“
,denworf kcom dna deggurhs daD
”.uoy ot netsil ll’eH
seye sih dellor eH
.llaf gnidnepmi na rof netsil ot
?t’nseod eh fi tahW“
,rufdaeh reh hguorht wap a debbur moM
,ti raeh ot ton dedneterp daD
,derewolg moM dna ahcaS htoB ".thgin
,deunitnoc ahcaS
.tluciffid gnihtyreve ekam dluow ti wenk eh fi yllaicepse
.thgirb til elims dna seye
”ydduB yeH“ saw sihT
.elbat eht ta gnippar swalc
tuoba stnerap sih dlot eh ecnis htnom a neeb d'tI
,elpmet sih ot pu tnew sregnif s'ahcaS
gnol os rof dehsaher tnemugra eht
.kcohs ni nezorf secaf rieht
.dexaler yeht dna emac reven tI
.gnireviuq eciov ,dias ahcaS
.thgirla eb ot gniog saw gnihtyreve
taht tuoba snoissucsid
.dnatsrednu ot mih tnaw I"
srae enipul xis lla
od dluoc eh lla dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy edisgnola
diputs snaem drow taht kniht ydaerla t’nseod eh ekil yag m’I
”,uoy etah reven d’eH“
.s’ahcaS sa emas eye sih delcric ruf fo tops etihw A
,kool taht ni wenk ahcaS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,meht tcartsid ot hguone saw tI
.VT eht no slennahc hguorht gnikcilf
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,won rof tub ,taht rof tihs eiggeR evig dluow moM
,rehto hcae otni erob serats s’owt ehT
.tsehc sih ni kcuts tog tsuj ti dna
gnihtyreve mih llet ot ydaer saw eH
,yas ot tnaem d’eh sdrow eht llA
,dekcud srae s’moM ”?dab ro
”ydduB yeH“   :yojne esaelP
.enod tsuj d’eh tahw ta dessarrabme ,decniw eH
.emitefil a fo gnidlocs eht rof ydaer ,seye sih desolc eH
,tif doog a eb dluow kniht uoy yrots a evah uoy fi dnA
,ynnuh esneffo on ,dnA
.kcab sih dniheb mih tuoba gniklat ekil t'ndid ahcaS tub
,deworruf worb reH
yawa etalp sih dehsup ahcaS .neht erofeb toN
”.stluda eht er’uoY
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no mih wollof dna
taorht s’ahcaS morf tuo delworg noitartsurF
.ylevol sdnuos eH
,mraw saw keehc reH
- h na htiw rieh s'taht - "rieH lebeR"
,meht fo htob ot deddon ahcaS
.taht od d'ehs wenk eh tub
.enohp sih otni kcab flesmih tup dna
.elzzum reh no ruf eht otni gnikaos raet sih
.mih llet ot detnaw I .yrros m’I“
.eiggeR htiw yawevird eht ni nwod tas d’eh
.gnilims saw daD
.pot no erew seitilibisnopser sih ekil
”.won thgir ti dnes I fi ,thginot ebyaM
.moM ffo seye sih gnikat tuohtiw enohp sih tuo gnillup
.ti no mih tcerroc nac uoy
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb ”ydduB yeH“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.gnitad detrats eh naitamlad gnimrahc eht ,nivlaC
,syawyna drawrof dehsup ehs tub
.eparcs yreve htiw gnihctiwt dna
.ecnelis eht htaenrednu ecafrus eht ot pu gniliob tnemugra na
.rehtnap emit-lluf a
,atros a ni pu dekcilf sworbeye siH
.mih ot txen nwod gnittis rehtorb redlo sih deretsiger ylerab eh ,neercs no desucof os saw eH
”,em etah ot mih tnaw t’nod tsuj I .did yllaer I
.seiromem yzah tnatsid ecnis gnol erew
,keehc reh ni dekcilc eugnot reH
.emoclew ton romuh fo esnes sih
.eillo na od ot rehtorb elttil sih hcaet saw
.dnim t’ndluow stnerap sih erus m'I os s’A thgiarts steg eH .mih txet nac I"
,t’ndluoc yllaer eh fi eiggeR ot klat d’yeht dias dna ecno edisa ahcaS dellup daD
,dias ehs ",gniyas m'I tahw ton s'taht wonk uoy kniht I"
,draobetaks sih no seillo gnicitcarp elihw toN
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,allevon a
.dnekeew siht nivlaC teem ot ekil erus d'I
,hcuoc eht no saw eiggeR
”?revo emoc tsuj nivlaC t'nac yhW"
.tnemugra siht ,ralucric emoceb d’tI ”.tsrif
.ti yas t’ndid eh tsael ta tub
mih dlot senomroh eganeet sih ni gnihtemoS
,eciov sih ni elkcuhc a ,pu dewollof daD ".mih
tnaw yllaer uoy od tub
.thgin eno taht sgod toh fo daetsni nomlas devres ew nehw kcatta traeh a dah ylraen yoB"
.yrt tsael ta ot dah eh tub
mih ot klat ot deen uoy yhw s’tahT“
.ti gnivah ton saw ,revewoh ,moM
.taes reh ni kcab tas dna guh eht desaeler ehs
.moor gnivil eht otni deklaw dna
.kaeps ot tsrif saw moM
,denrut eiggeR ”.yddub ,yeH“
.od d’eh tahw rettam on
”?wonk uoy ,thgir s’ehS“
.meht htiw tsenoh eb ot dah eh dna
,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
,levon a gnitirw si ,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.reve ot hcum oot uoy evol ew esuac ,taht wonk I“ .yltfos dias ehs
neht taht skniht eh fI“
enohp sih hguorht gnillorcs
,seye sih denepo eh nehW