.daeh ym revo swap ym esiar ylwols I dna
tnaem I ,yrros ,hgU"
"?ssertiaw eht morf eniacoc redro ot yrt uoy diD"
.em hcuot ot erehw yltcaxe swonk eh wonk I esuaceb ,ti etah I
,dneirf tseb ym s'eH
.hguone doog eb ot smees ,eelB
"'?hciwdnaS tahW' ,syas ynahteB neht dnA"
terces ytrid a saw ti dnA
.pu evag esle enoyreve nehw snoitidepxe etavirp no tneps saw devas ew yenom eht llA .ereht saw I
.su rof tuo telbat a htiw gup a ,dnuora semoc ssertiaw ehT
.eson eht no thgir mih gnikconk ,dliw sgniws tsif yM
.niaga lamron sa pu strats noitasrevnoc eht dna elbissop sa ylkciuq sa ti tsap wolb dna yrt I
don I .won kcab nrut ot raf oot enog ev'I tub
.eid ot sevresed enoyna kniht t'nod I esuaceb ,doog ton s'tI .gnissim tnew
,duol os era sexof ehT
mih ta yrgna sa t'nsaw I tub
",eromyna mih htiw tuognah ot tnaw I kniht t'nod I"
.spil ym tsniaga ssik rehtona secrof eh sa trofmocsid ym retsiger ot smees ylerab eH
.retteb elttil a gnileef m’I
.em no lla seye rieht ,gnihgual spots enoyrevE
.slrig hguorht seog htenneK tsaf woh htiw htnom eht fo rovalf eht tsuj s'ehS
.nug laer a ton s'ti taht ezilaer I od retaw fo hsols eht leef I nehw ylnO
?reklawruf emos uoy erA
.dlrow siht morf ton m'I dna ,kcaJ m'I ,iH"
"?daor eht fo edis gnorw eht no gnivird llitS"
llup I erofeb esuoh s'nonnaD dna em neewteb ecnereffid skcolb wef a s'erehT
,pu sehcnurcs elzzum siH .talf sllaf tI
,snoisnemid neewteb nevE
",enaC a evah ll’I kniht I"
,ekil ti saw tahW .gniht roop uoY"
esoht fo eno osla saw eh tub
,esuoh ym ot rood eht nepo I
.kcab s'erT dniheb dnuora gnikcuf fo aedi eht no ffo gnitteg eb ot desoppus m'I ekiL .detsiwt s'tI
.em htiw ratsdliW ees ot seerga kle ehT
.ynnuf ton s'taht ,rehtoM"
,nexiv eht ,sevael gup eht sa tsuj dna ,sknird rieht sredro esle enoyrevE
.dias tsuj eh tahw morf tliug laretalloc emos leef I dna ,pu og srae yM ".taht
".laed gib a ton s'tI
.keehc ym no kcep a rof ni snael
,yas ot sdeen eh sdrow eht s'tI
meht otni thgiarts deklaw I ,oga htnom a tuoba ,oN
,seye sih sllor ,sffocs eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.pam a em evag hctiw a esuac og ot erehw yltcaxe wenk dna
.elzzum reh ot ssalg eniw eht htiw taes reh otni kcab snael mom s'erT
"?nuh ,ot pu uoy er'tahW"
,redluohs s'kle eht segdun nexiv a dna nwod sdniw elbat ehT
,oot trihs sserd a no tup em edam eH
.sekib eht htiw gnissem seunitnoc eh sa dnuora nrut t'nseod eH
.rehto hcae wonk ew ekil taht yas uoY"
.ylyhs em ta gnikool ,fooh sih htiw nihc sih sehctarcs eH
,hU" .elbat eht no walc gib sih spat dna ni snael ,nonnaD ,raeb ehT
.tnereffid yna detcepxe evah t'ndluohs I dna
,hguone gnol ereh deyats I fi thguoht I .gniyl eht lla rof ,yrroS"
.stsixe taht em fo tsal eht eb thgim I kniht I dna
.nworf yrgna na ni detsiwt si elzzum sih dna
,ereht emag eht hctaw dna rab a ot og ot si thguoht tsrif yM
.yawa etsaw em hctaw enoyreve tel ot riaf t'nsaw ti
ekil d'I .ispeP a
"?uoy t’nevah ,oot siht tuoba deticxe neeb ev'uoy sseuG"
"?noisave xat morf serianoillim gnitcetorp llitS
enola tuo gnah ot gniyrt neeb s'eh tub
.gniliar sexof eht fo pu esolc a no kcuts s'ti won esuac ,gniht nmad eht ffo nrut tsuj eh rehtar d'I
,syas dna mom sih ot eralg a strad erT
.denetraehsid tib a skool eh tub
",noitidnoc sih fo trap tsuj s'tI"
.did I yaw eht raeb eht gnittih rof tsehc ym ni pu sdliub tliuG .revo
.em rof rood eht snepo raeb eht sa tuohs I "!yad emaG"
.eromyna pu flesmih dloh neve t'nac eh erofeb elbbow sgel siH
,rehtegot hctaw ot seivom emos tuo kcip ot eton a ekam osla I
.em dniheb rood tnorf sih gnimmals nehw tuo ti ekam yllaer t'nac I tub "!eson yM !kcuF"
tuo sehcaer eh ,hgis a htiW ".seil
,eil eht htiw evil ot gnivah etah adnik I
.kcab gniog ton m'I esuaceb
,oot emas eht er'yeht
".dlrow ym ot emocleW .erT si eman yM
mom siH .ymmut ym revo nworg sah taht eglub elttil eht gnittap ,yas I
.noitcif yrruf trohs gnitirw si
I dna dnalyensiD s'ti wonk ot sda eht morf hguone dnalredniC wonk I
.ti yas ot tnaw t'nod I esuaceb
ecneics retupmoc ni eerged a htiw yelekreB CU morf detaudarg I erehw
.tnemelzzup emos htiw syas nonnaD
a neeb syawla ev'uoY"
.hguorht enog sah erT siht sgniht eht tuoba gnikniht retaw seye ym ekam ot strats ti dna ,yas I
",eromyna rettam t'nseod ti sseug I"
nwodtup-flah .ekoj-flah gnikcom eht ni sksa mom s'erT
.ni em sdael eh sa syas eh
.nuf fo tol a saw tahT .haey hO"
.bos a hguorht tuohs I os dna
.ereh ti llac uoy tahw aedi on evah I ,hguoht
,sksa dna worbeye na skcoc eH
,noillats s'kciK hgiH eht tub
,og tel ot ytilibani eht saw derahs ew tahW
,dnalredniC etah I
.esnefed ym ot syawla ,syas erT
.erohc a adnik s'tI
,reve emit tsrif eht roF
.emag eht rof revo emoc uoy nehw od syawla ew tahW"
,sgniW dliW olaffuB ekil I" ,eunitnoc I os
.hturt eht em gnillet er'uoy ,emit tsrif eht rof kniht I tub ,rail lufwa
,trihs ym otni yaw sti sdnif wap A
.ylthgils ylno hguoht
,seenk sih neewteb daeh sih htiw roolf eht no s'eh nehW
,yltalf yas I ",gniworraH"
.daor eht fo edis tfel eht no sevird enoyreve dna
.retteb tol a gnileef m'I
.emag eht tuoba mih hcaet nac I os yadnuS txen revo emoc ot seerga htenneK
,skciK hgiH eht si maet llabtoof ym
.dnuora ylizal wap a gnivaw ,strats eh
,egde eht tsap yaw nekat neeb s'eH ".uoy
,snaem eh tahw wonk I ".semit
.tcejbus eht egnahc ot hguone s'taht dna
.gel ym tsniaga seporg eh sa tuo srettum eh
.egap emas eht no s'enoyreve os ti nialpxe ot sekil syawla erT tub
,em tcartsid snoisolpxe ehT
.ylreppihc syas eH
.ekatsim ym ezilaer yletaidemmi neht dna ,yas I
?tuo gnah reven ew did yhW"
,efeH lo doog ,knird ot desu I
.ecalp eht revo lla gniwolb knird eht ffo gnimoc maets eht ,strons kle ehT
.mih no gnihtyreve pmud ot tnaw t’nod I dna
.hturt eht yltsom saw taht dna ,dettimda I
,kaeps ot tuoba s'eH
.elohtihs taht ot og ylgnilliw reven d'I .stun yensiD
,dlrow ym ni kcab rehtegotla gnitae deppots I .eurt s'tI ".uoy
.erT ym ot deneppah tahw wonk t'nod I dna
wonk od I tahw tuB"
.hguoht wohs a no gnittup si yksuh ym taht llet nac I
.eludehcs ym dna ,gniht wen yreve
.rehtegot gnipeels erew yeht sselnu enoemos htiw sdneirf t'nsaw kcaJ siht —t'nsaw I
.pu uoy hctac emmel os uoy ot esnes yna gnikam si siht fo enon ,thgirlA
.mih sdrawot wap a tuo dloh dna ,plug I
.em htiw skcilc yllanif ti dna eussi eht dnuora gnitriks
.erT ot kcab teg ot enog ev'I shtgnel eht dootsrednu evah t'ndluoc eH
,tuo tnew sregnar eht emit yrevE
eh dna ,htenneK esimorp I
",kcab gnimoc er'yeht kniht t'nod I dna
",kcab og ot tiaw t'naC
.yot triuqs a s'ti suoivbo ytterp s'ti
.ria eht hguorht gnilias seog ti sa gnirednuolf ,cinap I
",ti gnihctaw pu dne t'ndid I ,hu ,hO"
rac rehtona otni tsrif daeh nur tsomla I litnu ton s'tI .teerts eht no tuo m'I ,ni teg I sa noos sA .rood
,tcefrep t'nsaw I
oga shtnom neves pirt gnipmac a koot kcaJ s’dlrow siht dna ,thgir hO
,net ni trats ot tuoba semaG
,flesym ot peek rehtar d'I snosaer emos rof dlrow siht ot og ot detnaw I ,eeS .hguoht ereh toN
.ta doog os s’ehs taht
.yrots ym hsinif I sa rethgual ni stpure puorg eritne ehT
,yas dna yksuh eht ecaf ot nrut I
",niaga og ew ereH"
.kcab uoy evah ot tsuj gnihtynA
,ereh ti od yeht woh wonk t’nod I
.rotucesorp etatS" "?niaga od uoy
,dneirf tseb ym saw htenneK"
.seil tub gnihton em dlot ev'uoy
.wenk syawla I tub
,tfel ym no raeb eht ot gnivom erofeb regnol dnoces a em seye ssertiaw ehT
.drawrof lotsip eht gnitsurht ,skrab eh
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoC triD wolloF
.ti eviler ot tnaw t'nod I
.ffo si gnihton ekil tca ot gniyrt ,syas eh
,yllausac sksa htenneK
.dnalredniC ta su fo serutcip dlo ta gnikool tsuJ"
”dlroW sihT morF toN m’I dna
feiler fo hgis llams a tuo tel I ".si
,edis eht ot elzzum ym kcoc I
.noitatskrow latem ykcolb a tub
won hturt eht uoy gnillet m'I tub
,pu esolc ti ta gnikool ,tcaf nI
.hcraeser ym gniod ton rof dab leef I dna
.niaga neppah ot gniog t'nsaw tahT
ti htiw gnola og I tub
,tpurretni I os ,ti esol annog m’I ,emit erom eno noitidnoc ym tuoba raeh ot evah I fI "—noitidnoc siH"
.semit ta eb nac kcaJ ynnuf woh togrof tsuj I"
,em ta nug a detniop eh taht ecin yrev t'nsaw ti ,naem I
.emoh kcab emoc t'ndid I yad eht hctib emos sdrawot erT gnirehsu deirt ylbaborp yehT
.drawnwod ylthgils detniop s'ti tub
,oot mih gnikcuf uoY
.drah taht hgual elpoep ekam ot elba neeb ev'I ecnis sraey neeb s'ti ekil sleef tI
ereh gnoleb I ekil don dna
,lla ta thgir em gnidaer ton s'eH
.ereh dnuora eeffoc fo daetsni redic toh sknird enoyreve tub
.gnorw gnihtemos did eh ekil
.daed ylbaborp si dna
,mih htiw tahc annaw od I tub
.pleh rof tihs lamronarap dna scihcysp ot gniog detrats I
,htenneK ym htiw sgniht riapeR
.oot taht ekil hgual eno siht ekam nac I ecnedifnoc em sevig ti dna
"?hsirT htiw sgniht s'woH"
hturt eht sevresed eh tub
",yadrutaS rof toohs s'teL"
"?syawyna mih htiw deyats uoy dnA
kcab gnihtyna dloh t'nac I
.hgiht renni ym pu thgir walc a nur ot niaga ni snael eh dna
,ecalp taht setah kcaJ yM
.eciov reh ni gnir ykrep a htiw sksa ehS
,rail lufwa na hcus m'I
.retaeht eivom looc eht ni tis tsuj nac ew taht dalg m'I
"?flesruoy yb lla ereht tuo gnieb
.em hguorht thgir ees dluoc eh nwonk ev'dluohs I
.nirg ediw a htiw reh ta pu kool I
,tnaw I ados eht yllautca ton s'tI
elpoeP .gniklat deppots I
".kcaJ ruoy ton m'I tuB"
",eciton reven d'uoy
.hturt eht timda ot decrof m'I sa gnikaerb traeh ym ,trats I
.erT hcaorppa ot diarfa elttil a m'I tub
,enim tsniaga pu gninnur s'tI
,etunim a rof ti tuoba gnikniht
reeb eht fo tnelaviuqe eht s'tI
.VT eht no esuap stih dna noisufnoc emos htiw etomer eht sbarg eH
,elbat eht no sreeb ym gnippolP
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
",rehtie sreh fo naf gib a t’nsaw I ,yllufhturt dna
sedud eht fo eno fo pals eht dna
,ytisrevinU drofnatS eht ta mehcoiB ".etatS
"dehsinav tsuj uoY"
"?emag llabtoof eht saw woH" .eerga I os
,ti tuoba kniht I nehw dna
.si hturt eht kniht uoy revetahw rO
.dias eh tahw ,haeY"
.sdoow esoht ni ereht tuo tluc xes emos denioj uoY"
.seye ym revo wap ym fo kcab eht gard dna ,hcnebkrow eht otni llaf I ".kcab
,htenneK ym llet d'I yaw eht
.ezingocer I taht eno ylno eht s'ti tub
.ecaf ym ot ylmrif dekcol spil sih
,kniht I ,etammoor egelloc dlo ym s'eH
.mih sdrawot wap ym tuo dloh dna
,gnihtyreve mih llet ot tnaw I
.oot enog si erT ym
",rehtie uoy no taehc reven dluow I esimorp I dna
.hgual lufitip llams a tuo gnittel ,eye sih sbur eH .timda I
.sotohp eht ni yfoog os kool eW
,eciov peed sih ni syas eh tub
elttil tsuJ .ot pu taht ssem t'ndluoc I os ti dias eh dalg m'I tub
,ecno ylno ksed tcerroc eht ot em leehw ot dah srekrowoc yM
.sdoow yna ni tsol teg t'ndid I ,eeS
.oga shtnom neves pirt gnipmac taht no tnew uoy
.denrael I nonnaD
.em htiw semag eht gnihctaw dekil yllaer reve eh fi htenneK ym deksa evah dluohs I ebyaM
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
"?ebab ereh nwod uoY"
,emoh gnimoC "?llabtoof hctaw uoY
.dessertsid os mih ees ot em gnillik s'tI dna
.saw I naht etanoitceffa erom tol a saw em s'dlrow sihT
.em ot esirprus a fo tib elttil a s'ti dna
.desufnoc si enoyreve won dna tsaf oot gnihtemos yas dna flesym fo daeha teg I
.spolf pilf dna trihs-t a ni emoc ot detnaw I hguoht neve
.etatS szatilaC ta ygoloiB fo rosseforp a er'uoY
.kcab gnimoc reven si erT yM
.emit siht VT eht no gnikcuf sexof oN
.od I yaw eht kcab mih kcep I
.taorht ym ni pu gnidliub sucum nwod ekohc I "—tsuj uoy
,morf m'I erehW" .nialpxe dna
,tuohs dna elbat eht no wap ym pals I
.mih htiw dnuorg eht no nwod teg dna
,ti yas ot tnaw t'nod I
.tnereffid si siht ,plehW ".ho
?saw erT laiceps woh wonk ton eh did woH .em rehto sihT
,sksa eh "?tuls elttil
.dnoces yna ffo og ot nug eht rof flesmih gnicarb s'eh ekil daerps sgel ,syas eh
,em dniheb nug triuqs eht tes I ".hturt
.hcuoc nwo sih no nwod mih worht ot ecrof hguone htiw kcab raeb gib eht hsup emit siht dna ,niaga tuohs I "!oN"
.tuo dnif ot hguone suorutnevda gnileef yllaer ton m'I tub
.ereh morf ton m'I tub ,kcaJ m'I"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.taht em remrof ewo I sseug I dna
,dluoc syawla erT yM
.yzarc gnihton s'ti tub ,keew eht tuohguorht sgniht wef a pu xim ylno I
.did ylbaborp I ekiL
.tnereffid gniht rehtona ,hgU
.elzzum ym elknirw ot ton tseb ym yrt dna
.tseb eht si htenneK esuac dlrow siht ni resol a hcus saw I ,naM
,sdneirf ym htiw etamitni os eb reven d'I
"?mriF" .gnisiar worb
.ti emocrevo ot hguone duol tsuj si sllab
,efil ym ,sdneirf ym pu evag I .sdoow nmad
.gnipeels deppots I
,esolc tops a kcip ,revo klaw I oS
.ydaerla tuo dnuof t'nsah erT woh aedi on evah I
,kcab uoy evah ot doog s'tI"
.edaf t'nseod elims sih tub
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,rac ym sdrawot pmots I
.nonnaD deman enoyna htiw tuo gnah t'ndid I dna
",retfa strops emos hctaw nac ew sseug I ,haeY"
.gniod saw I tahw s'taht dias I nehw llabtoof dehctaw yllautca I
,kcar ym htiw seussi ynam oot dah ehS .pu tilps eW"
,aloC-acoC a fo tnelaviuqe eht s'taht kniht I
.kcab llup tsomla I dna ,sreksihw eht no hsurb a em sevig ,ni snael nonnaD
elims ym no tup I ,llitS
,dab os gnikahs s'eH
,em rof ti eb thgim ti gnikniht ,flesym ecarb I ".seil
.pu dexim sgniht fo seman eht steg eh semitemos os dna raey a flah rof sdoow eht ni tsol saw eH"
.kcuf lla sa ygnilc adnik dna
,kcab pets yraew a sekat eH
.VT eht ta yltnatcepxe kool dna hcuoc eht otni nwod polf I
,setats eh ",sraey ni uoy nees ev'I tsom eht si sihT
.ereh nwod emoC !haeY"
,skcarc elzzum yM
.syawyna srettij eht tog I dna suoicipsus oot kool dluow tI
.esrevinu siht ni deneppah tahw erus ton llits m'I esuaceb ,yas I ",emosewa er'uoY
.dnalredniC ot og reven dluow kcaJ ym tub
.sgniW dliW olaffuB sevol dna dnalyensiD setah taht takreem eht ton m'I
ti si tahW .yrroS"
.dlrow siht ni sdneirf
.kcab srae ym dlof I dna
.revo ynapmoc evah yeht nehw od ot ekil yeht gnihtemos ,ecin desserd era stnerap s'erT .doom eht niur reh tel ot ton gniyrt ,ekoj I
.emit ot emit morf mih htiw od dluoc I gnihtemos ,ekoj I
.daeherof eht no flesym pals neht dna
.srekcaP eht si maet llabtoof etirovaf ym dna
.uoy rof gnikool sniatnuom esoht ni shtnom tneps I"
.llabtoof gnihctaw tuo saw eh dias eh nehw serocs eht wonk neve t'ndluow eH
.doolb gniward s'eh taht pil sih ni drah os gniknis gnaf ,syas eh
,enot deniarts a ni gniyas
,tey wap ym ekat t'nseod eH
—uoy gnisol esuac deyats I tuB
esoht ni gnikool deppots reven I taht yaw ehT .yaw lufwa
.yas I daetsni os
.eromyna em ta kool ot dnats neve t'ndluoc
.uoy rof gniyl enod m'I dna
,syas eh erofeb htrof dna kcab daeh sih sekahs eH
.tcejbus eht egnahc ylkciuq I ,rehtaf s'erT ot gninruT
sdoow esoht ni ereht tuo eb llits dluoc kcaJ s’dlrow siht ,kceH
.taht tpecca ot evah I
.tnemesab eht morf em llac erT raeh dna
,ffo er'taht sgniht
.noitanalpxe eht htrow ton s'ehs gniwonk ,yas I
na ni mih htiw detcennoc leef I dna
,yllufhturt esuaC
.sraet ym hguorht elbisiv ylerab s'eH
erahsecaF ,naem I
,ti ta dab gnikcuf os er'uoY !gniyl potS"
,diordnA na enohp ym llac I dna
.spoTeulB dellac niahc emos ,pohs a ta stniop htenneK
,morf m’I erehw skcubratS ekil atros s’tI
.emit eht lla htiw tuo gnuh I yug eht si nonnaD taht nrael ot emoc ev’I ,dlrow siht ni neeb ev'I htnom eht nI "?I t'ndid
",ereh yaw eht llA"
,hgU .em sdnimer eh
nug eht nwod tup ot uoy tnaw I ,ylhturt dna
,rettiwT no elbuort gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.htenneK 'lo emaS" ,hgual I
.sgniht htiw gnilddif
.uoy dnuof yeht nehw senob dna ruf erew uoY .teb I"
,debrutsid elttil a m’I ”?ay t’ndid
"—I erehw evac siht ot snoitcerid em evag hctiw A
erom eb ot mees yllausu sdneirf ruoY
.dam ekil gnikcuf sexof owt s'tI
,ssorg s’ti kniht I
.ni kcab reh gnirb dna yrt ot redluohs s'hsirT revo mra sih gnipparw
,acilper rorrim a s'taht gniht eno eht s'eH
tsuj I .yrros ,on ,oN"
.nug a nwo t'ndid erT yM
.kcar eht no sekib emos htiw renroc a ni mih ees nac I dna ,ereh nwod til ylmid s'tI
"?noitidnoc ruoy fo trap siht si rO
?pu gnidloh mrif eht s'woH"
.esle gnihton ekil em seracs tI"
,ylluferac syas eh ",deeps ruoy
,deraeppasid tsuj yehT
.hturt eht ton s'taht esuac ytliug elttil a leef I dna
"?nonnaD dna uoy htiw neppah gnihtemos diD"
.lleh taht epacse ot enog ev'I shtgnel ehT
.tuo hguoc I dna ,ediw worg seye yM
",TI POTS" "—noitidnoc yM"
"?siht si kcuf eht tahW"
.dlrow ym ni thgir sgniht ekam
.retteb gnihtemos rof tnuh eht no syawlA
",ti tuoba yrrow t'noD .pu dexim tog
,erT ym no taehc reve I did ecno ton tub
,koobecaF eb ot demees tsuj eW
,htenneK rebmemer I nehT
,dneirfyob lufrednow ym ,erT
.enim ni ti sees eh ekil seye sih ni ti ees I dna
",gnihtemos tuo erugif ll'eW"
?uoy era kcuf eht ohW"
.niaga edis ym yb yksuh eht evah ot doog sleef ti dna
.yfiralc I ",ispeP teiD a
.egnellahc a ton s'ti hguoht
,dleif eht nwod sdray ytriht resal a worht sregdoR noraA gnihctaw eb rehtar hcum d'I .eil I
",yadrutaS no stnerap ym htiw rennid gnivah er'ew ,tegrof t'noD"
,ylneddus dna evac a hguorht deklaw I
,desiar sworbeye reh htiw sksa ,kniht I hsirT
,kcab pets a sekat eh dna mih ta pu kool I
,dlrow ruoy morf m'I
,swap htob tuo puc I
,llabtoof ni detseretni t'nsaw eh
.sregnif sih neewteb ruop doolb ees nac I dna
,dnuorg eht ot si elzzum siH
",sey dog ho ,dog hO"
,doowyrrehc s'daD ym ton s'ti dna ,ksed eht ot nrut I
.tnemom eht ta em rof deniur si llabtoof tub
fo kcart peek ot desoppus I ma kcuf eht woH
.txen gniod fo kniht ot em rof sgniht noillim a s'ereht esuaceb ,si ti ebyaM
,peek ot esimorp gib a s'tI "?seil erom oN"
,hcuoc eht fo renroc a otni kcab ot gniyrt ,tuo maercs I "?edud ,kcuf yloH"
"?yadnuS rof no llits eW"
.tsehc s'raeb eht tsniaga gnihsup swap ym htiw
.gnikoj s'eh kniht I esuac hgual I
.pis a gnikat dna elzzum sih ot redic sih pu gnillup ,sdon eH
,yhtapmys emos htiw nwod dna pu daeh reh sdon ehS ".pu
.laed gib on s'taht tub
,mih ni sees em fo noisrev s’noisnemid siht tahw wonk t'nod I
.selcric ni sevooh sih gnivaw ,dias eh
.edart riaf a s’ti sseug I
egral si yksuh ehT
taes a sekat eh os ,rof gnitiaw m'I tahw wonk ot smees nonnaD
.esoprup no si eh sa hcum sa tnedicca no em toohs annog s'eh ylekil sa tsuj s'ti
ecaf sih fo sedis eht nwod gninnur era sraeT .gnikahs swap
.tuo semoc eew elttil a tub ,eil annog toN
,elavynnuS fo kcap xis a htiw esuoh s'nonnaD ta evirra I
.seil erom oN" ,taeper dna
.pot no eno eht ta tniop dna segareveb eht ot nepo gnippilf ,unem ym barg I "?kcaJ"
.syawyna nuf evah annog m'I dna
.mih dniheb llaw eht tsniaga pmub sreltna sih taht drah os kcab daeh sih sworht ,em fo tnorf ni kle eht ,htenneK
,srepsihw eh sa gnireviuq si pil s'yksuh ehT
,taht esimorp did I ,tihs ,wA"
.tnemeticxe hcum oot tuohtiw dnuora sllor yadrutaS
”dlroW sihT morF toN m’I dna kcaJ m’I ,iH“   yojne esaelP
".kcab gnimoc reven s'eh dna
kcaJ m’I ,iH“ saw sihT
"morf emac I erehw dnalyensiD ti llac ew tub
.ti htrow tub ,swolb tahT
",ksed eht ni sotohP" .enot yreehc emas taht peek ot em rof drah s'ti dna ,yas I
,t'ndid eh hsiw yllaer I
.wenk I" .syas eh
.tsehc ym fo tnorf ni tuo swap ym evaw I
"?taht rebmemer uoY
.esnepxe ym ta sekoj mom s’erT
.niaga evac taht dnif dna kcab og ylbaborp dluoc I
dessiM .kcab eb ot dalg m'I"
"?gnivah eb lla uoy dluow sknird tahW"
,wap ym ta skool eH
?uoy no gnitaehc saw eh wenk uoY"
redic elppa nomannic ym fo pis gib a ekat I ,hsinif I sA ".retteb
,tfel evah I erT ylno eht er'uoy taht si
.ma I tahw s'taht esuac ,duarf a ekiL
,syawyna mih tsol I"
"!ratsdlyW s'toiR guoD !haey lleH"
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
hguoht ,eromyna gniyrc ton s'eH
.em nuH gnikcuf uoy t'noD" "—nuH"
.der era seye sih
"?wonk uoy t'nod ,tuanortsa na m'I dnA"
.yfoog elttil a dnuos seod ti esuac ,shgual eH ".dlrow
.rood nepo eht no kconk dna sriats eht fo pot eht ot teg I
,erT ,dneirfyob yM
.noitcerid ym ti sessot neht dna
.hguone raf gnitteg ton tub
,tuo trulb I os ecnelis drawkwa na fo tib elttil a s'erehT
.gnihtemos em llet ot detnaw eh erofeb yllausu
,ekil gnihtemos syas eH
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.kool nrets a ni enim ot pu nrut seye sih erofeb
",kcuf teews uoy erem'C .siht dessim ev'I ,hhhhhO"
?taht ekil detnarg rof yksuh sih nekat evah em rehtona dluoc woH
eht ni syek eht teg ot gniyrt boj tniap ym pu eparcs yllacitcarp I
.tihs fo eceip desserped a gnieb saw I nehw tuo llef ew
,oot emit eht lla taht did erT yM
.mih sdrawot nrut dna daeh ym tfil neht ,yas I
.gnitae deppots I
,yllanoitnetninu hgual erT ym ekam syawla dluoc I
na hcus er'uoY" ,sehsinif eh tub
.taorht ym ni pmul a s'erehT
.hturt eht saw detnaw
!mih t'nerew uoy taht trats eht morf ti wenk I !ti wenk I"
.emag a gnitsoh saw I fi tuo spihc emos dah tsael ta evah d'I
.nwod dna pu don dna elims ym no tup I
.niaga daor eht fo edis gnorw eht no m'I ezilaer I taht
.niaga doog sdnuos htenneK htiw emit gnidneps
.nwod flesmih elttes ot gniyrt ,sevooh sih sevaw eh ",haey ,haeY"
nac I sa drah sa kcab llup dna cinap I
.niaga taht ekil em hcuot ot teg t'nseod eH
",gniod neeb ev'I tahw s'taht fi ,uoy kcuf annaw t'nod I ?seY ?ebyaM"
.dias ev'I gnihtyreve tuo krow ot seirt eh sa gnilffins llams a s'erehT
.wap a evaw dna elims ym no tup I tub
.erom rehtegot emit dneps ot su ekil d'I"
.taht lla dna ,llabtoof ,syug rehto eht ,nonnaD tuobA
,tuo klaw ew emit eht yb dna
,moor gnivil eht otni dael m'I .si retfa
.flesym ma I sa
,tihs ykaerf yllaer eht otni toG
:oot rail dab a syawla saw eH .rail dab
.elzzum sih no tnemelzzup etelpmoc fo kool a s'ereht dna
kcaJ s’dlrow siht taht dalg
.lla ta edisni gnihton ees I sa ezeerf dna eldnah reward gnol eht nepo llup I
,gnidnuop s'traeh yM
,em ta thgir eno gnitniop saw erT siht won tuB
,niorg ym ot sehsur doolB
—ni gnihton s'ereht ,nuh ,mU"
.tnereffid elttil a sdnuos eciov sih tub ,syas eh
,kcaJ ruoy ot deneppah tahw wonk t'nod I"
,thguoht ym hsinif nac I erofeB "—uf ehT" .yenom
.ylkciuq tuo tips I
,pu seog worb siH
,taes eht no tuo flesmih snethgiarts yksuh yM
.htenneK eb ot desu ti tub ,kniht I
I llA .yrros m'I"
,em ta pu kool ot sesuap eH "—mih
.syadawon htenneK htiw tuo gnah ot gnitnaw syawla er’uoY“
,deil I yrros m'I"
tahw erus yllaer ton m'I dna
,ecno ta lla nialpxe ot yrt dna ylduol plug I
,dlrow ym ni kcaB
era erusaelp fo snaom riehT
.ylhtooms rehtar no sevom thgin eht fo tser eht dna gniklat eht fo tsom od meht tel I
.tnemssarrabme htiw toh der srae
.hcuoc eht fo edis rehto eht ot sllor yletelpmoc eh sa emoh egassem eht tnes tI
,tuo lotsip eht tog llits s'eh llet nac I
”dlroW sihT morF toN m’I dna kcaJ m’I ,iH“
,siht ekil ecnahc dnoces a steg enoyreve toN
"?emag eht t'nsi sihT"
,ylthgit em dnuora mra na sparw dneirfyob yM
,syas dneirfyob ym ",noitidnoc sih s'tI"
.rehto hcae morf sehcni wef a tsuj era seson ruo dna
",mih ton er'uoy esuac taht wonk t'ndluow uoy tub
.elims tseb ym no tup dna seye ym llor I
"!deticxe m'I esruoc fO .sreniM azatilaC eht tsniaga skciK hgiH eht s'tI"
.ylthgit dehcnelc llits tsif
.wap ym spsalc dna
.mirb eht ot esolc ssalg eniw ym ruop I
".niaga tuo dekcik su teg annog er'uoy ,nuH"
.em gniyarteb ydob ym
.elbat eht fo elddim eht ni thgir tahs dna stnap ym delkcubnu tsuj I ekil s'tI
.llew sa og htenneK ym tel I esuac
.taht gniod yojne ot smees htenneK siht esuaceb
,esrevinu siht ni sdneirf gnieb ton su htiw sseug I dna ,yas I
,dnim ym sessorc thguoht dab A
",gnihtemos uoy wohs annaw I
.sbuc yna tnaw t'nod llits ew epoh I tsael tA
,emas eht enod s'eH
.tug ym ni sknis traeh ym dna ,syas nonnaD
.sruoh rof ecnelis ni ereht yats tsuj ew ekil sleef tI
,oot dlrow nwo ym ni resol a ma I sseug I ,lleW
"?yadnuS no emag s'kciK hgiH eht gnihctaw erew ew thguoht I ,yllautca
.ylsuoicilam ton dna
.taes sih ni selffuhs dna shguoc rehtaf s'erT
.gninetraehsid elttil a s'taht dna
,nedloG CU morf detaudarg taht kcaJ m'I
.uoy teem ot ecin s'tI .kcaJ iH"
,oot mih dlot I nehw deppots evah dluohs eH
.seye sih ni llits erised ,lworg ytsul wol a tuo stel eH
",erahs rieht edave t'nod serianoillim eht erus ekam I
.tops taht wenk erT ym ylnO
,dratsab gnitaehc a em siht saw ylno toN .ecalp taht etah
.dlrow siht morf ton m'I dna ,kcaJ m'I ,iH
.em raeh ylerab nac eh taht won ezilaer ylno I
".siht tuoba klat tsuj nac ew os
.eb ot ti tcepxe I naht rethgil
.nirg a htiw sksa eH
,etarepsed os tog I
.flesym tcelloc ot emit em sevig tI
.ti htiw regnif a ekat dna ffo og ot ti rof flesym gnicarb
.egnahc reven sgniht emos
tfel uoy nehw dnA .em toN
.mih htiw emit hcum os dneps ot gnitnaw em htiw driew elttil a eb tsum tI .sdon
.t'nac I tub ,emoh og ot tnaw I
,tib elttil a em detadimitni syawla dna
.retteb gniod trats ot deen I
.elbat eht fo tser eht seod oS
.elzzum ym otni peed eugnot enisru tew kciht a s'ereht
,srekaeps eht hguorht gniralb
.em no tuo eno deppihw d'eh dezilaer t'ndah eh ekil lotsip eht ta nwod skool erT
.meht fo lla ot esnes sekam taht noitanalpxe eht tsuj s'tI
llabtoof si llabtooF
em ot deil tsuj uoy dnA
?uoy era kcuf eht tahW
.gnimoc ti dah adnik I sseug I tub
tons pu trons I tub
.enoyna ot esnes gnikcuf on sekam hcihw
.spets eht gnidnecsed ylwols ,ksa I
.noisufnoc ni puorg eht fo tser eht ot seye reh gninrut ,sksa ehs "?tahw A"
.em ot revo gnitniop ,taht ta srekcins
mih raeh nac I dna ,kcab sllac eh
.emit siht ecnegilid eud ym did I dna
.detseretni t’nera erT dna em tub ,sdikdnarg detnaw syawla yehT
.kcab sreksihw hsurb dna
.dneirf lautca ym
?epyt ruoy saw reven I sseug I"
.emit tsal eno mih gniees fo epoh reehs eht rof tsuj ylimaf ym
.taht nwonk evah dluow eh esle
,ylkciuq sksa htenneK
,kcab neeb ev'uoy ecniS
,srettum dna gel ym ot wap a sehcuot
,elims a htiw yas dna revo nael I
.emit elgnis yreve sneppah sihT
,era uoy ohw wonk t'nod I
.esrevinu siht ot em ekat depleh ehs nehw desimorp hctiw eht erusaert eht
.etomer eht sbarg dna em ot esolc yllufwa
",ekoC a ekat ll'I"
"?siht tuoba woh oS
snepo wam siH  "!uoy saw tI"
elzzum sih gnihctulc era swaP
.pis duol a gnikat erofeb syas ehs
,os ,ecuas olaffub htiw puhctek decalper yeht tub
.flesym fo duorp elttil a leef I os
,yls os saw eh kniht ot desu eh —desu uoY
",em fo egatnavda koot dna
"?nomed fo tros emoS
.hturt eht ot resolc hcum taht gnitteg s'eh wonk em stel taht sklat eh taht yaw eht ni gnihtemos tsuj s'erehT
.eil a s'ti ekil leef adnik I ".sseldrager
.gnorw os mih debbur rednulb ym yhw ees nac I dna ,yltnulb syas eh
,syas dna ssenireehc ym ta elims yhtoot ediw a sevig eH
,seivom fo naf gib a yllautca ton m'I hguoht dna ,mrifnoc I
,skcans yad emag on s'ereht taht gniciton
.gniog dah eh tahw niur annaw t'nod I dna
mih ton s’eh tub
,htenneK esimorp I
.gnorw s’eh deveiler yltsom tub
,sdap wap ym tsniaga yltfos sknalc tI
",doof laer gnitae
.detcurtsnoc ev'I eil elohw siht ,llac esolc a ekil sleef syawla tI
.noitasrevnoc eht pord ot gnitnaw ton ,ni snael hsirT
.rethgit lotsip sih spirg dna ,syas erT ",doG ot raews I"
.ton ylniatrec s'ti ,oN
.rof gnikool s'eh tahw sdnif eh litnu slennahc eht hguorht gnippilf ,neercs eht no skcilf eH
.raeh ot deen I sdrow eht sa hcum sa tsuj
mih dewo ti ekil kcoc sih gnitaeb s'eh sa tuo smaercs dekcid gnitteg eno eht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ti nwod gnidils ylwols dna llaw eht tsniaga gnipmuht
dlrow siht ni dna
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.selppin ym ot thgiarts ruf ym hguorht gninnur swalc
",kniht uoy tahw ton s'tI"
.wenk enoyreve taht
”,em tsuj s’tI .tca eht pord nac uoy ,kcaJ“