,yppah etiuq ton ,leef
.ecaps eht ni tuo sgniw reh koohs ehS .ffo
.meht neewteb ecaps eht dellif ecnelis ehT
.htiw nigeb ot reh ni saw taht detah ehs tuB
”.mottob eht ta ereh kcab ynapmoc tog ev’uoy tsael ta ,lleW“
.niap fo ytilibissop eht htrow saw niaga yppah eb ot ecnahc eht gnikaT
.evA ,demahsa os m’I dna efil ym tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’I
.erofeb erew ew ohw
.deneppah ti retfa yltrohs ti tuoba wenk I
.tuo yrd meht gnittel dna
”.esoppus I ,lairotirret …s’tI .haeY“
.sgnitsop boj rof gnikool eb dluohs ehs ,ereh kcab gnieB
,liart eht hguorht edor yrevA
.krims a otni detsiwt ecaf s’etoyoc ehT ”.ti teg t’nod I
”niagA emoH“:yojne esaelP
.detsixe ehs dlrow eht llet oT
.ton ro em tsurt nac uoY
.seinapmoc tnereffid dnasuoht a ot semit dnasuoht a dedivorp ydaerla d’ehs noitamrofni emas eht rof deksa taht noitacilppa rehtona fo ynotonom leurc eht tuo gnipyt
.hcamots dna tsehc reh revo nur sdnah reh gnittel dna
.mih htiw gnipeels saw ehs ,shtnom wef a retfA
.thguof yeht nehw rebmemer dluoc ehs tuB
,rae sih dehctarcs eH
.delims yrevA ”,haeY“
.deksa ehs ”?taht s’tahW“
,did ew tahw tuoba ,su tuoba
.dehgis eh ”,haeY“ .dias ehs
”.rekorb tnemtsevni na s’ohw elcnu ym ot gniklat neeb ev’I ,hu yllautca I .taht tuobA“
”.uoy gnitruh rof yrros m’I
.no gniog saw tahw aedi on dah ,ecno rof ,yrevA …t’nsaw sihT
.gnihtyna dias I tegrof …tsuJ“ “—caasI“
,og flesreh tel
.ereh kcab saw yrevA ,sselehtenon ,tuB
,mih ta dekool yrevA
”.snoitpo tuoba uoy htiw klat ot ekil d’eh dnA
.niaga esu I stcatnoc dna slliks eht esu reven ot teg I“
,gniklaw peek ot meht rof derutseg eH
.ecin yllaer si uoy htiw ereh gnieb tsuJ“
.ekil uoy gnihtemos dniF
.rehto hcae ot klat ot detnaw llits htob yeht dna
,snrut eht otni denael ehS
,kcab daeh sih denael caasI
”.dneirf ruoy eb ot gniyrt tsuj m’I
,mih fo kniht ot tahw …erus t’nsaw ehS
sessenisub dna srotsevni fo htlaew eht htiw etats eht gnidoolf saw taht yenom wen eht lla etipsed
hcrop tnorf eht ot tnew ehS
”?gniod uoy era tahW“
,gnol os roF
meht neewteb lamron taht ro doog taht eb dluoc sgniht taht
.delims yrevA ”!taerg s’tahT“
,dias ehs ”,uoy knahT“
?thgir ,rof si llac taht tahw s’tahT“ ”.rettam I
.yks thgin eht ta pu gnilwoh
daeh reh ot yaw rieht dnuof sdnah egral esohT
.dettimbus saw noitacilppa txen eht dna
.dnomaid llabesab eht tsap ,eiriarp eht hguorht gniog
.nosrep retteb a eb ot gniyrt m’I dnA
.siht gniod peek ot daeh reh truh tI
.nwod dna srehtaef tfos reh gnileef
.dnik dna gnipleh er’uoY
.semitemos teg dluoc uoy lla saw retteB .retteb tub
.gnihton yletulosbA .gnihtoN“
.uoy tuoba erac I esuaceb uoy pleh dna yrt ot deen I dna
,yrc dehsiugna na tuo tel dna
.mra sih pu tnew taht stsirw sih no skram gnol ehT .ruf dna niks sih otni gud dah taht
,ot deen I nehw ereh gnimoc peek em tel uoy sa gnol sA ?tahw wonk uoY“
”,llac a fo lleh a s’tahT“
foor ro sllaw on htiw doow fo eceip talf a taht tuo detniop d’ehS
”.esnes sekam taht fi ,ecaep ta
,dehgis ehs ”,yrros m’I“
sterces reh mih gnillet
”.egats taht tsap htob er’eW .t’nod esaelp
”,tnemom eht rof ni gnimoc yenom emos peek nac I tsael yrev eht tA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.seye sih tih t’ndid kool eht tuB
.seye sih ot kcab dnah sih morf
.pohs eeffoc eht fo renroc eht dnuora deunitnoc dna pets rehtona koot eH
.rac reh otni tog ehs sa reh pots ot hguone reh rehtob t’ndid ti tuB .wonk t’ndid ehS
.yrros m’I“ .revihs reh edam
pil sih no gniwehc saw eH
.elims tfos a htiw reh ta revo dekool caasI tub elbidua neve ylerab ,teiuq saw tI .dias ehS
,noitseuq hguone tneconni na saw ?thginot rennid barg annaW
.sraey ynam os rof detah d’ehs enoemos fo tsehc eht otni gniyrC
?eh t’nsaw ,emosdnah saw yllaer eh esuaceb mih ta delims llits ehs tub
.noitcnitsid taht tuoba derac eno on tub ,esuoheert a ekam t’ndid
er’uoY“ ”.raeh ot ecin s’ti
.si taht yhw tuo erugif ot gniyrt m’I …tsuj I dnA
”,ton ro ti eveileB“
,daeh reh deddon yrevA
.looc gnieb tuoba t’nia ti ,lleW“
.em ot netsil ot gnilliw er’uoy fi
.sreh dezeeuqs dnah s’caasI
.gnihtyna xif lliw siht gniyas ton m’I
.tsiaw sih dnuora smra reh devom ehs dna
,siht naht uoy ot esle gnihtyna yas reven I fI
.rennid retfa ekib reh no saw yrevA
erehw ecalp eht ot kcab emoc ot dah I .em del efil ym erehw si sihT
.degnoleb ehs erehw
.sdnah reh fo htob htiw daeh sih otno dleh ehs dna
.ekortsyek yreve ni regna htiw gnipyt
.erom gniklat trats nac ew ebyam dnA
.mih ta daeh reh dekcoc yaj eulb ehT
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
…hcum ssim t’nod I“
.ydob reh dekcar sbos sa revo dehcnuh
.em ot klat t’nod uoy fi dnim neve t’nod I
.dexif yllacigam eb ot su neewteb sgniht gnitcepxe ton m’I“
.doow eht fo pot no bmilc ot hsurb eht hguorht gnipmart
snaej fo riap ecin a dna trihs depirts a ni
.kaew os gnieb rof flesreh detah ehS
.tnemom gnol a rof mih ta dekool yrevA
.nalp a tuo erugif ro
,gniliar eht tsniaga kcab denael ehS
ni detneuqerf d’ehs pohs eeffoc dlo eht ni tas yaj eulb ehT
,ti fo dnuos eht ta derevihs yrevA
.sreh ot ydob sih fo
.mih htiw gnineppah saw tahw erus t’nsaw ehS
.yltfos spil sih dessik dna
.reh otni thgir derob
.keehc sih dessik dna mih dnuora smra depparw ehS
.ti no dnah reh tup dna
.tsehc s’caasI otni daeh reh denael ehS
”.ti wonk neve t’nod uoy dna ylkciuq os uoy morf yawa pils nac sgnihT .ti otno dloH
.seye reh gnignits sraet eht gnileef
”?em pots uoy lliW
.seye eht ni thgiarts reh dekool eH
.evA ,uoy ekil yllaer I … I .flesym nekorb
.ereh kcab emoc ot dah I .epoN
eciov eht sdrawot pu dekool ehS
?detnaw ehs tahw tuo erugif ot drah os ti saw yhW
.redro reh decalp dna
”.tib a rof srats eht hctaw tsuj s’teL“ .delims dna
.gnitruh htob er’eW
”?elihw a rof dnuora kcits I fi dnim uoy oD“
?ti rof wohs ot evah I od tahw dnA
”…litnu sdneirf ym htiw gnifrus hcuoc saw I
.erusserp eht leef ton dna
sgnirpS odaroloC neewteb ecaps eht saw taht erutluc fo dnal s’nam on tsav eht dah uoy ,dnoceS
”?haey ,dnuora uoy ees ll’I tuB
.gum eht no gnippat sdnah denniks-hguor reh
.em tsurt ot nosaer a evah uoy yas t’nac I oS“
”.niaga gniklat detrats ew ecnis uoy ot deil t’nevah I .hturt tsenoH
.dennirg yrevA ”,haeY“
.taebtraeh ydaets sih ot gninetsil
.depleh rehtegot emit riehT
.tnemom a rof caasI ta dekool ehS .dias yrevA ”,haeY“
.loohcs ni reh tsniaga detsiwt d’eh taht
.sedis dna tsehc sih debbur ehS
,mih was ehs nehw rO .tnaruatser eht ta rac reh dekrap ehs nehw rO
dnabsuh a sa seruliaf sih no luos sih derab d’eh dna
… ot dedeen tsuj yehT
.eno tsal ym ecnis shtnom 6 neeb s’ti tub gniht siht morf teg I skool eht etah I
.kcab efil reh detnaw ehS
tuo dehcterts erew smra reH
.dleh eb ot doog os tlef tI !doG
.pu kcuf reh derongi enoyreve woh saw siht fo lla htiw melborp ehT
”.erofeb uoy llet t’ndid I
”.siht detnaw reven I
,yawa teef net ton ,was yrevA ,pu gnikooL .dias eciov a
.uoy pleh ot gniyrt tsuj m’I …tsuj I
,yawa noitacifiton hcae depiws bmuht s’yaJ ehT
,no sehtolc reh htiW
?gninrub llits erew esoht fo ynam woH
.stnerap ym dna uoy tub nwot siht ni enoyna wonk t’nod I
.tihs a evig t’nod yehT
gnipoord sredluohs sih ,daeh sih ot talf erew srae s’etoyoc ehT
wollaws ot reh rof tnemom gnol a koot tI
yawa pils lla noitartsurf dna ,niap dna ,regna eht tel
.tnemom taht rof efas dna
.did uoy noitautis emas eht otni nar ohw elpoep htiw dekrow s’eh tuB
.nwotnwod pu edam taht spohs desolc eht tsap derednaem yehT
.eman eht saw ereht ,tsriF
.niaga erehwemos gnoleb I ekil leef I .enola kcuts
reh yrd pleh nus eht tel ot gniyrt ,tuo sgel reh dehcterts dna
.ti desolc tub reh htiw eugra ot fi sa htuom sih denepo eH
.gniraelc eht ot hguorht tog ehs ,krow fo tib a retfA
.niap saw ereht tuB .ecaf sih ni ytip ro regna yna t’nsaw erehT
”.krow naht swen retteb hcum s’taht …s’tahT“
”…I“ ”?uoy ot riaf dnuoS
.hcnarb eht no delttes tog dna
”.uoy ekil tsuj I dna teews dna lufpleh gnieb tsuj er’uoy tub ,sgniht etacilpmocrevo I .sgniht knihtrevo I
sdrapoel dna shateehc neewteb ecnereffid eht gninialpxe dna krow yrruf gnitirw neeb s’eH
.ecaf reh ni dniw eht gnileef
.kcatta ot dediced ehs fi evael ot ydaer ,mih dniheb toof eno dah eH .dias eh
”?yawa deppils ew ekiL“
yeht t’ndid dna elbatrofmoc leef ot reh detnaw tsuj yeht dna
.pets-dim ni saw gel sih dna
,llirt a evag yaj ehT
.efas …tub das ,ylenol
uoy ekil I taht uoy llet ot deen I
.sdrow reh ta worb a dekcoc etoyoc ehT
.niaga mih dessik dna
.ti raeh ot tnaw t’ndid ehS .enod saw ehs
.ereh deppart tsuj m’I
.sevitom roiretlu on ,esle gnihtoN
.uoy wenk I nehw flesruoy fo erus dna tnedifnoc os erew uoY“ .dias ehS
,siht uoy llet ylno nac I tuB
dleif eht ni eb ot teg reven ll’I dna tihs peed ni deppets I
.dleh gnieb saw ehs dna
.boj ruoy naht erom er’uoY .evA ,rettam uoY“
”.dnop gib a ni hsif llams yrev a ylneddus saw I
”?ti rof teg I od tahw dnA .yenom noisnep htiw gniod saw mrif tnemtsevni eht taht tnemelzzebme eht detroper dna gniht thgir eht did I oS
.deworran seye reH
”niagA emoH“ saw sihT
.etoyoc eht ot kcab depyt ehS ?dnim ni evah uoy did erehW
…tsuJ .gniht eruS“ —derebmemer ehS
”?yakO .flesruoy evigrof ot deen uoy tuB .uoy evigrof I
”.moorhtab eht ot og nac I os trohs elttil a klaw siht tuc ot deen ew kniht I oS .gninrom siht eeffoc fo tol a
”.og annog m’I kniht I ,mu ,I …sseug I
.gnihtemos dias I nehw em otni wehc dluow taht tiw gnitib
.llac etag ykaeuqs eht gnignis dna
dehgual etoyoc eht ,daeh reh morf srehtaef reh detlom d’ehs nehW
.moor eht fo tuo dekcus saw ria eht ekil tlef tI
fo tsap a otno gnignilc saw ti ekil demees syawla hcaocegatS tub ,drawrof gnivom saw ti ekil demees dlrow ehT .revneD dna
.eiriarp eht hguorht htap gnipols eht nwod gniog
.tsap ainnellim fo srats gniknilb eht ,srats eht gniees
secalp rof ylppa ot gniyrt eb dluohs ehS
.niaga reh gnissik
.ycnega gnitekram a rof gnikrow boj siht tog ehS
tlef tsuj gnihtyreve dna esuoh a rof pu gnivas erew eW .deirram tog eW
.ssob reh rof em tfel taht eno eht s’ehs nehw egairram eht deniur I taht yrgna er’yehT
.uoy gniees peek ot tnaw I …I oS
.doow eht fo pot no kcab dial caasI
elbat eht ssorca denael yrevA “—
!doog erew sgnihT
.sreh no llits dnah siH
epoh dna emit ekil tlef tI
,ecnetsixe reh fo tcaf reehs eht ecrof ot deirt ehS .truh dna lamirp
.tnemom gnol a rof ecaf sih revo dekool dna ngis eht ot kcab denael ehS
mih etah ot detnaw yllaer ehS .mih etah ot detnaw ehS
gniod eb dluohs ehS
”,oga syad wef a ereh tog tsuJ“
.yawa htaerb ym koot taht ereht epoletna siht saw ereht dna
tuo epav sih koot eH ”…em dlot ehS
htaerb gnol a tuo tel yrevA
,eert eht no dnah reh tup yrevA
”?thgir ,ereh gniod er’ew tahw s’tahT
mih htiw emit dneps ot elba eb ot depleh tI
,ecnis noisufnoc fo sraey ynam oS
evitroppus dna dnik os erew yehT
.ralimis gnihtemos evah I tub
.daeh reh deddon yrevA
”.yltcaxE“ .mih ta delims ehs
.deddon eh dna daeh sih ot deppord srae gib esohT !srae sih tub
.dnah sih otni gnilzzun
,thgiew reh rednu detfihs yehT
.on maercs ot egru eht thguof ehs sa detsiwt hcamots reH
…tsuj ot uoy detnaw I
.eybdoog yas neve t’ndid eH
.ti ot pu deklaw ehs ,ylwolS
tsuj si em fo trap elohw tahT
?taht wonk uoy ,sraey ni taht em llac ot nosrep ylno eht er’uoY“
.saw I kcuf eht ohw tuo erugif ot gniyrt ,sbulc tnereffid wef a ot gniog detrats I“
,daeh reh deddon ehS
dnats eht dekcik ehS
…tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’I …I“  .reh dna
,enola ,teiuq ,tas ehS
.hgual a tuo tel dna tsehc sih devohs ehS
.niaga em truh ot gniog er’uoy taht daeh ym fo kcab eht ni raef siht evah I
hcum os gnikaerc dna gnivom
m’I …m’I .gnihton ma I .gnihton …evah I
”.ereh kcab eb ot tnaw su fo rehtieN“
”.taht rof uoy knaht
.won elihw a rof tub ,yadot tsuj toN
.em deyortsed tsuj ehs dnA .neht yb raey a tuoba rof deirram neeb d’eW
.eromyna ytic taht ni evil ot tnaw t’ndid I ,dnA
sgniw reh gnivom ,sriatsnwod tnew yrevA ,daetsnI
.tnemom a rof thguoht ehS
.uoy ot netsil ot ton em gnillet speek taht em ni gnihtemos evah I tuB
…I os gniht eno tsuj naht erom er’uoY
.rehtegot yrotsih rieht lla tuohtiw ,elpoep lamron erew yeht fi sa mih htiw dnuora yalp dna klat dluoc ehs taht
.htnom tsal boj ym morf ffo dial saw I
.thgif taht fo og tel ot emit emos reh koot tI
evah t’ndluohs I
ecalp taht otni gnihtyreve tup I
.ydob eritne reh ezorf eciov ehT ”?yrevA“
.pu sserd t’ndluow ehs tub ,mih htiw rennid ot tuo og d’ehS !eniF
.eert dilos eht otni denael dna dehgis ehS
”.tey uoy gniveileb ot pets taht ekat em tel t’now taht em ni gnihtemos s’ereht ekil leef I tuB
”?naem uoy od tahW“
,yawa gnileef eht derevihs eH
demahsa reh edam eH
.derettam ehS .degnoleb ehs
.seiromem ynam ooT
.ot did enoyreve erus edam dna
.fo erawa neve t’nsaw ehs skeehc reh no sraet eht revo bmuht a dehsurb eH
”?yakO .uoy sserp ot gniog ton m’I tub uoy dloh annog m’I
.dluoc ehs sa tseb sa siht hguorht mih pleh ot detnaw tsuj ehS
”.nwot ni kcab erew uoy wonk t’ndid I“
dnuora gniod uoy era tahW“
.mih fo etsat dna
.dleh yeht tub kaerb yam yeht thguoht ehs
.mih was    ehs dna drawrof dekrej daeh reH
ecnayonna htiw deworruf saw worb reh dna teiuq saw yaj eulb ehT
”,haeY“ ”.lwoh a ekiL“
”,uoy htiw m’I nehW“
,gnihtyna gnipleh t’nsaw hcaocegatS ni kcab gnieB
sdraob wef eht detnalp d’yeht hcihw no eert delrang ,dlo eht fo evruc eht was ehS
.ereh kcab saw ehS
.yrevA ta gnilley deppots daeh reh ni eciov eht dna
…uoy detah I nehw neve ,caasI“
sreh ni ti gnidloh
.taorht sih gnivael hgis a
,revo gnilaeh bacs a
.egelloc ot tnew I ,lleW“
.neeb evah reve I kniht t’nod I …yrevA ,nosrep yppah a ton m’I“
,yb gnissap enoyna ot suoregnad tahwemos tca eht edam naps gniw egral reH
.rehtnap emit-lluf dna ,retirw emit-trap a s’ohw
…siht tuB .ni kcab deppots ehs nehw semit wef a lwoB eldooN ot enog d’ehS .ni reh gnidael
.dekrims ehs ”,hguoht epav uoy eveileb t’nac I“
.ezigolopa ot deen oN“
.drah oot krow I …tsuj I“
…s’tI .oga sega taht yb gniog deppots I
dednuos taht did seiceps reh yrc egnarts eht otni
.tih ot erehw wenk eh esuaceb saw ehs ohw fo
.elihw gnol a rof sdneirf erew eW
.dias caasI ”,yrevA yeH“
”?doog dnuos taht seoD
.teef ruoy no kcab teg uoy pleh si od ot tnaw I lla tuB
.elpmis saw rennid rieht rof ydaer gnitteG
tnev dna klat dna
?yltnecer derevoc yeht t’ndah cipot tahw ,lleW
,oga sraey ynam os htiw sdneirf ecno saw ehs etoyoc ehT
suoitcefni ylevitisop saw elims reH
dleh eb ot doog os tlef tI
?wonk’y ,thgir ,tlef tI .doog
.lagelli gnihtemos gnitroper rof boj ym morf derif tog I“
”.esnes tcefrep sekam tI“ …daetsni tub
.ward ro yrtsudni rojam yna t’nsaw ereht tub
.duolc kciht a ni ropav eht delahxe eH
.mih ta revo kool a gnikat
won thgir gnileef er’uoy revetahw ot netsil ot gnilliw m’I
.sraet kcab deknilb ehs ,nwod gnikooL
.mih was ehs litnu
”?yako ,ecaep ni eeffoc ym knird ot gniyrt tsuj m’I
,seye reh desolc ehS
,dnah sih koot yrevA
nwod yek retne eht demmals ehS
.hguorht deeps ot elba saw ehs liart ekib eht saw ecalos fo eceip eno eht tub
.elihw a rof detfird tsuj I oS
,delffur gniw reH
?mih fo suoicipsus os ehs saw yhW
.won nepo dekcarc saw
.sdraob eht fo pot no pu doots yrevA
.noitnetta ruoy teg ot gniyrt neeb ev’I“
.yrtnuoc eht fo noiger siht ot evitan ton drib a eb ot llits reddo saw ti tub
…tsuj tub tsap eht tuoba toN
kcab reh revo debbur dnah s’caasI ”.enog llA
.doow dlo eht tsniaga talp a htiw tih pord hcaE
ecalp a ot ,ylbacirtxeni ,dnuoB .degaC .depparT
erehw tniop eht ta erew yeht kniht t’ndid tsuj yrevA ,yltsoM
.denworf caasI ”?taht s’tahW“
.denworf caasI ”,haeY“
.sburhs dna sehcnarb fo elbmarb kciht eht hguorht teg ot tniop eno ta lwarc tsomla ot dah ehS
.dnuora daeh reh dellor ehs dna
.desserd gnitteg emit reh koot dna
.og secrovid sa raf sa
.rehto hcae ta demaercs yeht nehW
.gnola emac ssob wen reh neht tuB
”?gnihtemos em esimorp uoy nac tuB“ .dias ehs ”,yakO“
.eromyna boj ym tuohtiw ma I ohw wonk t’nod I .gnihton dah I
.tnemom eht rof tnemom eht ni eb ot elba demees ehS
.mroftalp talf a edivorp ot
.dehgis eh ”,thgirlA“
sih ot desserp kaeb reH
”.tiuq ot elba er’uoy yppah m’I
.suoivbo eb ot ton tseb reh gniyrt dna
.yrotirret reh sa siht gniralced ,gniog tpek ehS
.kaeb reh dehcnip dna dehgis ehS
”.sdneirf ton er’ew tuB“ ”.evA ,uoy knahT“
pu dekrep erew srae egral siH
.snaem siht tahw erac t’nod I
os shtnom wef a ni em ta elims ot nosrep ylno eht
eeffoc fo gum a dah eH
…m’I ekil leef t’nod I“ .dias ehs
,mih pots t’ndid ehS
.revo steerts wef a evil llits stneraP
.ton ro kcab em ekil t’nod uoy fi erac t’nod I dnA .emit gnol a rof uoy dekil ev’I
.moc.yrrufos.ybigrek//:sptth
.sih ot desserp daeherof reH
.reh deracs taht dnA
.ti detah ehs dnA
?pool a hcus rof reh gniworht ti saw yhw tub
.dias caasI ”,yakO .hO“
?reh htiw no gniog saw lleh eht tahW .oga edaced a tsomla gnisu deppots ehs eman a reh llac mih tel ehS .mih tel ehs tuB
,taht evah t’nod I …I .haeY“
.yletelpmoc yawa og ot uoy detnaw ,reven ,reven I tub ,nossel a nrael
taht neerg fo edahs ecreif a dna tfos erew seye siH
,pu pets evitatnet a gnikaT
,em morf gnileef emos edih ot evah uoy kniht uoy fI“ ”?taht s’tahW“
leef reh ekam ot rewop eht dah llits taht
.ylwols daeh sih gniddon dna reh ta gnikool
.ereH tuB .odaroloC tsuj ton ,hcaocegatS tsuj toN
.elihw a ni neeb d’I naht reippah saw I ,lleH
”.yaw ruoy gnidaeh kcul doog emos tog ev’uoy raeh ot yppaH“
,nworg dah nwot ehT
.taht htiw yako eb ll’I
htoob eht ffo kcab reh
”.dneirf ruoy eb ot tnaw tsuj I .niaga uoy morf hturt eht edih ro eil reve t’now I
.enoyreve delffab taht eciohc a saw retaeht eivom llams eht morf teerts eht ssorca letoh ecnerefnoc egral a gnidliub dnA
,ylthgit dnah sih otno dleh ehs dna
,eeffoc reh fo pis a koot ehS
!ti od dluoc ehs stnemom esoht rof ti htrow saw ti tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mih emalb t’ndid ehS
flesmih esopmoc ot dedeen emit eht gnikat
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.thginot denessel dah mih gniees fo gnits eht llet dluoc ehS
.erus ,taht dna krow no sucoF
.taht tsap og t’ndid eh tub
.regnol tib a ereh tuo yats ylbaborp ll’I“
.og tel gnieb yllanif saw ti ekil leef
.uoy pots t’now I“ ”.yppah eb ll’I
.erehwon og dluow erus saw ehs noitacilppa rehtona no gnisucof ,won rof txet eht derongi yrevA
.hgis peed a tuo gnittel dna daeh sih gnitser
,tnemom gnol a rof ti no werd dna
.rehtegot nwot eht hguorht deklaw caasI dna yrevA ,rennid retfA
.mih ta detrons yrevA
.retteb leef reh ekam dna yrt ot enod d’ehs tahw gnirongi ,no srednilb tup ot demees enoyrevE
”.siht od ot loot drah-yrt emos ekil gnikool htrow s’tI …oS
”.uoy od os ,sknahT“
.reh no desucof eh tub ,dleif eht ni gnihtemos fo dnuos eht ta dehctiwt srae siH
.reh ta revo dekool caasI
hcuot eht otni dexaler ehs dna desolc gnirettulf seye reh
…trapa llef egairram ym ecnis revE
?neppah taht did nehW
”.won thgir t’nac tsuj I .timmaD“
?taht reh ksa ot saw eh kniht eh did ohW
.sevruc reh degguh taht pot a dna
.nekorb saw reh tuoba gnihtemoS
.eromyna mih morf raef ot gnihtyna dah ehs ekil leef t’ndid ehS
”.yrevA ,dneirf ruoy gnieb ta ecnahc dnoces a tnaw I
.srekrowoc dlo reh morf stxet dna segassem eht hguorht gnillorcs ,enohp reh debbarg ehs
,drah deladep ehS
,ecnahc a em evig uoy fi oS
.syawathgiarts eht no gninrub sgel
…em ot did gnirif eht dna snoitcejer eht revetahW .rettam I
.derevihs ehs dna trihs reh rednu dekrow sdnah siH
eloh lleh siht ni deppart m’I .caasI ,deppart
.neht kcab uoy dekil I esuaceB
!retteb leef ot tnaw t’ndid ehS
.drah deladep dna
.uoy truh I taht ekil t’nod I
,seye reh desolc ehS
.fooP ?gniht thgir eht did I nehw neht dna
hcamots reh no sdnah sih fo gnileef ehT
*** .ruos ylneddus demees eeffoc reh fo etsat ehT
.kcab emac reven ehs erus ekam ot drah os dekrow ehs erehW
.pleh thgim ti thguoht tsuj I .gnihton yletulosbA .gnihtoN“
.taerg s’taht ,yllaer tub
.ecaf sih no elims tfos a dah eH
,knurt eht no kcab sih denael eH
.etoyoc yhtrowtsurt ytterp a er’uoY“
.kool eht evah ot detnaw tsuj yeht
”.did I tahw rof em etah dluohs uoY .yrevA ,em etah dluohs uoy tuB
.hgis txen sih ta deredduhs ydob sih dna thgit desolc erew seye siH
.rewohs eht morf ffo gniyrd llits srehtaef reh ,no sehtolc reh deppils yrevA *** .taht htiw yako saw ehs dnA
.hsurb eht hguorht yaw reh dehsup yaJ ehT
…leef I nwot siht ni ecalp eno eht si siht tuB
.noitazilageL gniwollof ni emac taht
kniht ot reh deracs tI
,loot drah-yrt a ekil gnikool ylno rof uoy fo nuf ekam thgim I ,yliranidrO“
.niaga ereh saw ehs tuB
”.oN“ “—nac ew ,pu hctac ot tnaw uoy fI
.yllanif saw evol tahw wenk ehs taht em dlot ehS“
detcurtsnoc-ylroop ehT
.ylerecnis os reh ta gnilims saw eH
.yks krad eht ta pu dekool yrevA .dias eH
tsuj dna og tel ot ecin os saw tI
.klawedis eht fo edis eht no
,mih ta dekool dna
”.evA ,emoclew er’uoY“
”?ti toG .ereh thgir gniyats m’I“
.ti ta gniraet dna ralloc sih gnibbarg derebmemer ehS
.lortnoc esol reh edam dna pu reh dellif regna ehT
?sseug I ,ti ekil tcA .wonk t’nod I
.evitcudorp gnihtyna
.dias ehs ”?yrroS“ ”?evA“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
?gnola emac taht gniht tsrif eht sa mih otno gnihctal tsuj ehs saW
.caasI ta revo gnikool tpek ehs tuB
.deretlaf yrevA ”,caasI-
,pu dna pu dekool ehS
.revetahw ro tcennocer ot ereh ton m’I ,kooL
ap nwo ym ta siht od ot woh tuo erugif ot deen I tuB
”,seiromem ynam ooT“
.ni gnikrow sraey 01 tsal eht tneps I
.ecaf reh gnidih edahs ’seert eht
tneced yawflah dekool thguoht ehs taht stnap elbatrofmoc debbarg tsuj ehS
”.lufituaeb s’tI …s’tI“
.etag ykaeuqs a ekil
,dias yrevA ”,no oG“
.delims eh ”,ecin kool uoY“
!melborp eht saw tahT ?ti teg
toh erew skeehc reH
.mih morf eerf gnillup
,won skeew wef a rof rehto hcae htiw emit gnidneps neeb d’yehT
.daeherof reh no yltfos ssik a detnalp eh dna
,enog ecnis-gnol saw hcaocegatS eman eht nesohc yllanigiro dah reveohW
.tsehc ruo ffo teg ot deen ew taht su gnirehtob s’taht tihs yas ot elba gnieb dna gnitnev tsuJ
.evA ,neht uoy ees ll’I .looC
*** ”.neht kcab teg s’teL .hcoop ,thgirlA“
,detsisrep ti tub ,ecalp siht morf yawa devom dah
.flesreh ot gnihgis dna edisa meht gnivom
?yako ,taht no llewd ot uoy tnaw t’nod I“
.era uoy wonk I .era uoy wonk I“ .daeh reh koohs dna dehgis ehS ”…I“
.eman elbirret a hcus emaner ot elihwhtrow ti thguoht reven dah
.saw ehs ereh tub siht ekil kaerb ot epyt eht t’nsaw ehS !kaew t’nsaw ehS
.mih ta dekool ehs regnol eht
.reh fo tuo ti gnirb ot eno eht saw eh taht detah ehS .nwod peed
mih rof traeh reh ni dah llits d’ehs regna eht taht wenk ehs tub
.rehtegot doohrobhgien dlo eht hguorht ecnelis ni deklaw riap ehT .dias ehs ”,eruS“
.ytip on ,ecivda oN
,slamina evah ro mraf neve t’ndid elytsefil taht devil ohw elpoep eht fo tsom taht tcaf eht etipsed ,gnimraf elpmis
uoy esimorp I tuB
.uoy htiw klat ot ekil d’eH
?emit emas eht ta tub ,tespu m’I dnA .enog
knard I“ .sreh ni sdnah sih fo htob dleh ehS
ssik tfos a htiw pu mih tuhs yaj eulb ehT “—
.detsisrep ecalp siht yhw gnirednow tpek yaj eulb eht ,emit elohw eht dna nwod-nur dna rellams tlef tI
.niaga tops siht ot nwod gnimoc saw I“ .dias eh
.pu hctac yllaeR .pu hctac
.ydob mrif sih fo pot no ruf tfos eht ,mih tlef ehS
.ekorb yllanif ehs yad eht mih ta gnimaercs derebmemer ehS
.nwot ni kcab m’I elihw krow gnitlusnoc emos gniod boj a tog I oS“
,etats eht fo trap siht ni drib a gnieb hguone ddo saw tI
tsuj ot doog tlef tI
.reh ta gnikool ereht doots
”.krow naht tnatropmi erom hcum m’I“
.reh ta dekool caasI
,riap eht ot pu emac adnap der redlo nA .dias caasI
.oga sraey ynam os ti gnipacse retfa kcab reh koot efil reh erehw saw siht taht detah ehS
,no deggard ecnelis ehT
.tnedifnoc os erew uoy ,elohssa na erew uoy nehw nevE
.morf epacse ot drah os thguof ehs erehW
.stnerap reh htiw emoh ta gnieb eldnah t’ndluoc ehs tub ,stnioj eht no 04-DW fo stnuoma larebil tup dna niahc eht lio ot dah d’ehS
mraw erew spil siH
tuB …flesruoy rof taht od nac uoy ylno ,uoy evas ro xif ot gniyrt ton m’I
tnew dna emac laem riehT ”.seod yllaer tI“
.srehtaef reh hguorht og ria eht tel dna sgniw reh daerps d’ehs ,dnuora saw eno on tnedifnoc saw ehs nehW
reh dnuora evom smra siH
.won thgir pu dekcuf elttil a …htob er’eW“
.rof saw ti tahw saw siht tub
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sdneirf owt tsuj saw siht ;etad a t’nsaw sihT
,derettam ehs erehw saw sihT
,kaeb reh ot pu dnah sih thguorb ehS
.nrut ni eh dna semit wef a nwod nekorb d’ehS
.og gnittel ton dna tsiaw eht dnuora mih gnidloh
.lufniap dna ylgu
.niaga yrt ot dna kaeps ot ecnahc a uoy gnireffo m’I tuB
,erofeb mih detsurt d’ehS
nwod nur dna ,dedworc erom demees gnihtyreve taht yaw eht saw ereht ,drihT
.elahxe wols ,gnol sih ni
.mih ta kool neve t’ndluoc ehS
.caasI ,esle gnihtyna od t’now I .hsssS“
”.caasI ,taht ekil gnikaerb rof yrros m’I“
.melborp ym fo trap s’tI
.ti morf ffup a koot dna tekcop sih fo tuo epav a dellup eH .dias eh ”,haN“
.pu ekib reh tes dna
…em no pu welb gnihtyreve nehw taht reerac ym no desucof os m’I
.won rof yad ecin eht yojne tsuj ew tuob woh ,nehT .yakO“
”.erus ton m’I“ .mih ta kool dna
spil sih no ssik tsal a decalp yrevA ”.em
,mih ta dekool yrevA
,drawrof denael caasI
.og tel ehs fi evael d’eh diarfa
si yrots s’yadot dna
!ton ro evitan ,ereh pu werg ehs ,llits neve tuB
.tnemom a rof revo etoyoc eht dekool yaj eulb ehT
.eerf saw ehs litnu
fo kniht dluoc ehs terces yreve mih dlot ehS
seog siht erehw ees ll’eW“
”.niaga yppah ot kcab teg reve ll’I kniht t’nod I dna
”.sseug I ,ekil tlef ti tahw nettogrof tsuj d’I
sracs peed eht was ehs nehw depsag yrevA dna seveels gnol sih no seveels eht pu dellor eH
”.uoy derehtob evah ot yrros m’I
.rehtegot ni devom ew ,egelloc retfA“
tsehc reh no saw taht thgiew eht fo emos gnileef
no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,mih htiw ereht tis ot ecin saw tI
.pu tuhs ylbaborp dluohs I …I …uoy knahT“
”.egnahc a rof thgir gnihtemos od nac I yppah m’I“ .dias caasI
,niaga daeh reh koohs ehS
.pu sevlesruo kcip rehto hcae pleh dna
mra sih debbarg ehS
”.ygolopa ruoy tpecca I“ …tuB
thgiew gnitfihs eht ta dekaerc doow ehT
.htrow s’taht lla rof ,eman ym no
,ylthgils depoord sredluohs siH
pets rehtona koot ehS
.ecaf reh depiw dna
.yad ecin eht yojne dna klaw a ekat d’I thguoht tsuj I oS
”.wonk t’ndid uoy fi uoy fo tuo tol a sekat egairram deniur A
,esuoheert dlo eht ot kcab yaw rieht edam yeht ,yllautnevE
…noitseuq eht tub
”.yks taht ssim I tub
.reh etad ot detrats I ,nehT
eno ot tnew I ,lleW
.taht reh llac enoyna tel t’ndid ehS .evA dnA
gniyrc morf der skeehc
,rood eht denepo caasI
senots suoiracerp no decnalab dna sedacaf enots eht no pu depmuj yehT
…elttil a gnileef llits m’I
.derettam hcum taht pu gnisserd
.sega ni dah ehs naht reerf dna rethgil gnileef ,delims yrevA
yruf fo tnemom siht dah ehs taht detah ehS
?erehpsomta eht tih llits thgil rieht tub
,dnuora mih gnivah deyojne ehs dna
.txet eht fo noitaunisni eht ta
.egelloc sih morf eidooh dedaf ,dlo na ni sdnah htiw ereht doots eH .caasI
.esle enoemos eb ot flesruoy wolla dna emoh og tuB
.sessik tfos dnah dna sregnif sih evag ehS
hcuot tfos eht ni seye reh desolc ehs dna
?thgir ,tihs dradnats ytterP
.klaw a gnikat tsuJ“ ”?ereh
,tnew ehs reverehW
dluoc ehs tseb sa ffo nwod reh deird d’ehS
…tub ereht tuo yats ot elba eb d’I thguoht I
.krab hguor eht revo ti gninnur
erofeb snoe tuo deid ynam woH
”.tnaw uoy fi em nioj ot emoclew er’uoY
…tsuj ehs tub ,reh rof thgif ot deirt I
.pets rood tnemtrapa ym ta tfel slamina daed dna staerht htaed teg I
esolc mih gnidloh
”?uoy ot deneppah tahW“
”?retfa er’uoy ti s’tahW ?yhW“
”?taht htiw yako saw I fi em ksa uoy t’ndid yhW ?niaga htuom ruoy gninnur er’uoY
”.evA ,tsurt eht nrae I erus ekam ll’I
.siht fo ekam ot tahw erus t’nsaw ehS
.tsehc sih no daeh reh gnitser ,mih tsniaga denael yrevA
mih ta delims yaj eulb ehT
ot tol a snaem tI .yrevA ,uoy knahT“
.esruoc fO .on ,haeY .thgiR“
?thgir ,taht morf em tcetorp dluohs swal rewolbeltsihW
stnemnrevog nwot dna sraey gnidecretni eht tub
?ecalP iahT ehT .lwoB eldooN
.yltfos reh gnissik ,delims eh
.sselhtrow dna kaew
htuom reh denepo ehS
.taht detah ehs dnA
.ecaf elohw reh pu til dna
.reh detnorfnoc I
.yrevA ,uoy ekil I ,si hturt …hturT“
.niaga uoy ees ot ecin s’tI
tlef ti ,doog tlef tI
.0102 ecnis
,ybigreK ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb ”niagA emoH“
”,yeh tuB .yawa rehto hcae dehsup eW“
.sehsub dna seert fo elbmarb kciht a dnuora pots a ot emac yrevA ,yrotirret railimaf tA !evila
.og tel dna mih htiw elims tsuj dluoc ehS
.desiar selkcah s’etoyoc eht dna
.keehc reh dleh eh dna
.uoy llet ot evah I gnihtemos evah I nehT“
”.eromyna ekil sleef yppah gnieb tahw wonk t’nod I …wonk t’nod I
”?oga skeew wef a morf eno ehT
?llet I dluow ohW
…os s’tI .woW“ .dias ehs
dnuora denrut etoyoc ehT .hcnarb ybraen a ot pu depmuj dna sdraob eht no toof eno tup caasI ”.sknaht …tsuJ .ti teg I ,haN“ ”.sdneirf er’ew naem t’nseod siht
yks eht neewteb htrof dna kcab tnew dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ybigreK yb
.reh ta gnikool ton
?gniod er’uoy kniht uoy od tahW“
.ereh saw doohdlihc reh fo ”esuoheert“
.pleh ot detnaw I esuaceB“
.caasI ta dekool yrevA ,ni gninaeL
.meht ot tnatropmi gnihtemos gnisol fo niap eht ro thgif rieht dah reven d’yeht ekil saw tI
.edis eht ot dekcoc daeh siH
.erofeb did ehs sa mih ot esolc sa tlef ehS
.wohstihs a ,yldlim ti tup ot ,saw hcaocegatS fo nwot ehT   ybigreK yb
.gniht nmad a naem t’nod setats krow ot thgir tuB
”.yddaD dna ymmoM oT .tsen eht oT
.meht rof sunem htiw retal tnemom a kcab emac ehS
.eromyna ma I kcuf eht ohw tuo erugif ot gniyrt m’I …tsuj m’I .I ma oS“
.meht neewteb llaw elbartenepmi na
.rehtegot srats eht gnihctaw dna
,elbacima …saw tI .pu tilps ew oS
.kcab emac adnap der eht nehw delims yaj eulb ehT
.gnits eht rebmemer llits dluoc ehs tub
,daeh reh koohs ehS
sracs eht revo tnew swalc reH
.htap eht ni tilps a ta deppots dna
.llew yrev em tsurt ot elba eb ton yam uoy …uoy wonk I
,htoob eht ni kcab gninael dna gnihgis
,gnieb reh ,yrotirret reh
.reh ta denworf caasI
”?tnaw uoy od tahW“
.devaw dna mih ot elims elttil a evag ehS
.yawa devom ehs erofeb syad eht
;esrow eb dluoc tI“ .dias ehs ”,haeY“
.boj tseb eht gniod ton saw ehS
”!epyt eht rof uoy derugif reven I“
seye reh gnisolc ,mih dessik ehS
.caasI ,pu gnihctac eb ll’ew kniht t’nod I“ .dias ehS
”.uoy rof noitisoporp a evah I“
.ecin sdnuos taht ,haeY .haeY ?krow 6
.llaf sraet eht gnittel
siht dah ehs dna ,trams dna ynnuf saw ehS
.staes rieht ot meht gnidael
.riah reh hguorht sdnah reh gninnur ,dehgual ehS
I“ .yfitnedi ot gniyrt saw eh dnuos a edam d’ehs fi sa
.eromyna setteragic gnikoms ton tuoba s’tI
.dekil yllaer reven d’ehs emoh a saw tI
segdirb rednu tnew ehS
,ylwols daeh sih deddon eH
.tsal eht t’nsaw ti tub lortnoc fo tuo raf taht neeb reve d’ehs emit tsrif eht saw tI
.daeh sih deddon caasI
,reh morf emac ti nehw dnuos taht detah yrevA