.dedeen yletarepsed
yobdooG ydduB yb
noitarepooc ruoy rof sksa niatpac ehT
”.ypoc t’ndid I ?Q“ .koohs mE
.mE ot kcab denrut neht ,segap emos hguorht demmiks meht etisoppo hcysp ehT
reenoiP htommam eht morf yawa sruoh erew yehT
.rewolfnus revlis taerg a
,stcnitsni rieht tsniaga ,lla ti hguorht dna
”,siht od ot desu t’ndid eW“
,ytiC anuL dna ,tibro ranul ot pihs esiurc a ,noitatS htraE ot eluspac A
,sruoy naht tuo rehtraf yrtnuoc a ot gniog m’I ,sediseB
”.egrahc ni m’I elihw yawa gniylf uoy evah t’now I
”.reenoiP eht ees nac uoY“ .dias enoemos ”,tikooL“
.klawecaps a gnikat yllanif nehw evren rieht tsol ohw nemecaps tuoba seirots erew erehT .tuo dna
.won thgir esrun rehtona deen t’nseod rotcod s’pihs ehT“
.ylerab ,dluoc yehT
,kcilliK yb uoy rof daer
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.delevart yeht hcihw hguorht muidem eht gniwonk ton tub gniees
.ti dessim mE tub ,gnihtemos dias Q
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
ereh lla s’ti dna
.yrolg elbirret sti ni gnihtyreve saw ti
.ti ni tuo saw mE
hcysP tub ,yzarc er’uoy yas d’I
.esruoc sti gnola setiroetemorcim tub gnihton saw ereht
deppat dna elif s’mE fo mottob eht ot dellorcs hcysp ehT
.worbeye na dekcoc cod ehT
”.t’ndluow uoy esruoc fO“
* * *   ”.ecaps ot gniog er’uoy yas d’I os
”.srotamalcer xif ot woh wonk t’nod uoY“
,gnitoof sih tsol
.gninnur peek ot deirt dna deffup mE
”?meht detcepsni ev’uoy llit meht tsurt uoy dluow tub ,muucav dna dloc eht ot pu eb ot desoppus er’yehT
,ecalp a saw sihT
,uoy ot deepsdoG
,detset dna ,deborp ,deparcs ,debbaj ,deddorp ,dekop saw mE   * * *   ”.devorppA“
,riahc eht ot dennip regnol on erew yeht taht erawa emaceb mE dna
.sdnah artxe deen did yllaer eH
nac a ni delaes lla
erew serots s’pihs eht fo tnuoma eguh A
”.dlo sraey eerht s’rac yM“
”,esrun a er’uoY“
”.yad gninoitar s’noitces ym saw yadoT .yrroS“
,level citoiborcim a no efil ot dlrow eht thguorb
,lios gnivil ot trid daed nrut ylwols ot elba
”—redro ni eb ot smees gnihtyrevE“
,kcilliK yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
pu delaes ylbatrofmoc yats d’yehT
.sraM ot meht yrrac dna
.emit siht srotamalcer eht kcehc ll’I .emit ruoy ekaT“
.ecalp fo ecnesba na ton
”.reenoiP eht ni teg ll’uoy parc dennac taht naht retteb ,ria hserF
.ereht tuo ten ytefas on s’ereht—
.god retsam noegnud eht
”.ytic eht ni kcuts m’I ,neht litnU .pu snepo eno ecno yrettol eht ni m’I .srevird rof pac eht tih kcolb yM
”.tuo daerps ot moor erom stoL .oot
.ereh thgir tnaw uoy gnihtyreve evah uoY“
.gnihtyreve was yeht tub—
.ekauq ot nibac eht fo dlrow eht gnittes
”.dik ,edistuo daeh ew erofeb tius ruoy kcehc nac I os llits dloH“
”dlrowemoH“   yojne esaelP
.arabraB .tS ot reyarp sselhtaerb
.hcysp eht htiw seye dekcol mE
.saw ti ereht tuB
.raey txen eht rof emoh ruoy eb lliw reenoiP“
,ydaerla ereht stsinoloc eht rof dehsinelper seilppus dna
.meht hcaer dluoc yeht tlef mE dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tfil rof uoy deraelc
.retsamretrauq eht dias
.mih eveiler dna hctac ot elba saw reciffo hctaw txen eht litnu
.stniartser taes rieht tsniaga yltneg gnicnuob daetsni
’.eht‘ reh llac t’nod uoy ,ydal a s’ehS .reenoiP tsuJ“
,detcepxe sa ,saw erehT .dlrow wen a ot
.laes eht dekcehc dna ralloc thgitria eht otni temleh rieht dettols mE   * * *   ”.trats ot tnaw I
ffo deppord neeb lla dah
.siht uoy ksa em tel oS .mE—“ ”.mE“
.hguoht doog era erusserp doolb dna etar traeh ruoY“
kootrevo elbmur peed a neht dna ,niatpac eht morf tnemecnuonna ynnit A
.tnatsissa s’retsamretrauq eht eb ot dereetnulov mE taht saw ti oS ”…llaftenalp
,edisni smrowhtrae eht morF
,ssengnihton tsav saw ti
* * *   .emoh ti yrrac dluow senigne raelcun sti dna
”.ereh gniyats ni emahs on s’erehT
”.llaftenalp ekam ew ecno doog emos od em tel lliw draob no sledom wen eht xif ot woh gniwonk ,sediseB .nrael ll’I
desucof dna dellews ylwols srehto eht naht tod rethgirb A
evitarepooc taht t’nsaw arreT rehtoM—
.emitemos yrtnuoc eht ot tuo teg dluohs uoY“
.seye sih revo dnah a nar eH
,reverof gnillaf saw ecapS
”.setunim wef rehtona pu deeps ruoy peeK
.tneitap doog a eb ot deirt
.tneitapmi gnitteg saw mE dna
.llac no rotcod eht dekramer
,gnuh sratS .nepo ediw
.ti fo lla ,retaw ,negyxo ,doof ruoy ,seibab ruoy dnA .sgniht ruoy fo erom ,uoy fo eroM .sklof uoy rof edisni ecaps erom detnaw ynapmoC eht tub“
,kcab dna woleb morf derednuht senigne s’tekcor ehT .gnihtyreve
?tey krow AVE rof detar neve uoY“
,retsamretrauq eht delbmurg
noitatS htraE morf depmup thgil eht hctac dluow nrets s’pihs eht ta lias ralos ehT
.ksir syawla si ereht—“
,reviecer oidar a riaper ot klaw yksir a nekat d’ohw
”—ni tnedicca elttuhs a neeb t’nsah erehT“
saw ecapS .moor nepo gib
saw sihT      …daer ot ikahK rof ysae s’ti os stnedni on htiw lairA stp61 si siht dna ,thgin ymrots dna krad a saw tI   .emoh erew yeht
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.raef tub gnihton draeh d’yeht
snrettap rehtaew dellortnocnu ,esaesid ,tsevrah dab A
.daeh rieht morf thguoht lla dezeeuqs dna taes rieht ot mE dennip hsup tnaig A
.tenalp wen a otni detcejni eb ot ydaer
,ni kcab ria sti dehtaerb pihs ehT
.esool tel ot hguone doog er’uoy kniht I litnu stoob citengam ruoy esU“ .ecnahc ot gnihtyna evael t’ndid
.riahc eciffo eht otno deppolf dna revres s’eciffo eht otno selif deppord mE
.nepo delcyc hctah kcolria eht ,ecnelis ni dna
.ezeeuqs a ti evag dna
.moor ytpme taht lla htiw od d’uoy tahw swonk droL
.liar ecnanetniam eht otno flesruoy eruces ,ekas s’dog rof dnA
,yobdooG ydduB yb ”dlrowemoH“
.ytiniffAruF no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.delworg hcamots s’mE
.stsirw dna kcen s’mE ta sgnittif eht htiw delddif Q
.ecno ta sregnessap eht tih tnemeticxe eht tub
.tius erusserp ruoy rof deifitrec teg dna hctaw eht fo reciffo eht ees oG
.derettam taht yaw yna ni ton
.god retsam noegnud eht
.rae rieht ni dezzub gnihtemoS
”.kool taht tog uoY
,sprat yb detcelfed erew esoht fo tsoM
,nees lla d’yeht epahs eht otni
”?htraE evael ot tnaw uoy od yhw ,ksa ot evah I
”.serots negyxo ruoy dniM
detfil thgiew eht
,yllaniF .delims dna
.ecalp ni senil ytefas rieht dekcol dna hctah eht hguorht meht depleh Q
.raey a rof draob no eb ll’eW“
,taerg a saw ti ekil tlef yeht ,daetsnI
seborcim dna ,stcesni ,trid htraE
nemecaps laer tub
d’yeht sA ”…pihs wen a ngised ot naht muucav rof srotamalcer nedrah ot repaehC
,dlrow-ffo neeb reven d’yehT .emoh saw
”.ytic eht edistuo tinu gnisuoh a dna rac a evah uoy teb I
reenoiP htiw gnimoc srelttes wen os ro derdnuh eht ecnO
.wef oot dna ,egakaerb ot enorp ,dlo saw srotamalcer fo kcots riehT
,erusopxe muucav morf edisa dna ,flesti erehpsomta retne reven dluow reenoiP
ll’ew dna llimdaert eht ffo poH .neht
evolg s’mE rof dehcaer retsamretrauq ehT
pihs eht fo hcaer fo tuo tsuj nups dna
”.yadretsey saw eniM“
ecaps htiw enola eb ot teg I ekil sleef tI“
.lluh eht ot dehsal yrenihcam fo spmul htiw detraw eb ot sevlesmeht dewohs pihs eht fo senil naelc eht
.eno rof desnecil er’uoy tuB“
”,siht hguorht tis t’ndluow I“
,yobdooG ydduB yb ”dlrowemoH“
.stnemelttes eht no sesrun deen syawla yeht dnA“
,emit tsal eht rof ssenkcalb eht otni ylwols gnidecer ,erehT
,gnillifer deen ot gniog era esoht lla
,htraE gnicaf selohtrop eht rof thgif a
.ecaps yllaer t’nsaw nooM ehT
emoh ees t’ndluoc mE
”.reenoiP eht ot elttuhs eht ni eid neve dluoc uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.ereht tuo doog emos od nac I
.revo lla tuo daerps ot selim fo snoilliM“
.gnikrow saw wolf ria eht erus eb ot tsuj ,elttil a depsag yehT
.gnillaf ekil leef t’ndid yehT
.efil rof tif yllaer ti edam dna
.mrifnoc ot eciwt oidar s’tius rieht dekcalc mE
,ria rehserf dna
,tuo dna ,pu dekool yehT
.yltneg dehgual Q ”.em rof tsuj
hguoht ,uoy nraw ot degilbo m’I
.sevil retrohs evil srelttes taht tcaf a s’ti—
.ecnanetniam deen lliw tnempiuqe gnimraf eht dna
,hguoht ,xo na sa yhtlaeh er’uoY
,yad gnol a neeb dah tI
sraet yawa deknilb mE .htraE
,yad tsrif taht reenoiP ot resolc nettog
.seitivitca draobpihs htiw tsissa ot deksa eb lliw uoy fo ynaM
”.ksir eht htrow era sgniht emoS“
,retal ytinrete nA
,scinopordyh eht rof sdees ,doof ,yramrifni eht rof enicidem ,seirteliot ,sehtolC
.nrut rieht tog mE
yaw rieht no erew yeht—won laer saw tI
srelttes eht hcihw
.stset rehto emos ot no evom
.deddon hcysp ehT
?ti t’nseod ,thgir sleef ti ,dias I“
esrevinu eht htiw ecaf ot ecaf doots mE
.erofeb sraey nooM eht morf sdneirf rieht lla morf sdractsop nettog d’yeht tub ,tfig noitaudarg a sa nooM eht ot noitacav A
,sixa sti no leehwnip dluow reenoiP
,tfarc gnidnal a ot tuo derrefsnart yeht litnu
srotamalcer eht tub ,elbahtaerb saw ria ehT
.ti tuoba thguoht mE retfa esnes edam tI
,kciuq a dias dna stniartser taes rieht dekcehc-elbuod mE
,etingi dluow mets s’rewolfnus eht
,esruoc fo ,nosirraH
,sward dna setirw ohw
.yawa meht evaw ot deirt dna
,daeh eht fo kcab eht ot woble prahs a retfa tub
.ytilibats dna tnemtimmoc mret-gnol ni detseretni s’ynapmoC eht tub ,etargime ot deifilauq ylsuoivbo er’uoY
nopu tiderc ni diap eb lliw robal taht gnidnatsrednu eht dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,tnemelttes eht rof doolbefil eb dluow srotamalcer ehT
.sediug ruot yb gnola dediug dna
.taht swohs drocer ruoy ,krow drah ot regnarts a ton er’uoY“