ksed smrof eht raen nac egabrag eht ta detniop I
.ecilps-ammoc a si ti esiwrehtO
.lluf ti dellif seno dna sevif
”.ecin yrev yllaer s’ehS“
,tius yarg a ni regit ehT
".diap sllib ruo htiw ereh fo tuo klaw htob lliw I dna uoY .em tsurT
.hcnul dednetxe ,ylrae lausu sih rof rood eht tuo deppils eH
,hcinniM dieR yb ”egatsoH“
”?tnatropmi taht saW“
.ssalg eht revo ti dessot I
"?ynnoK" .drac eht daer I
”?ecnalab eht ees nac uoy taht yfirev esaelp uoy dluoC
si yrots s’yadoT dna
?su fo htob rof hguone ti saw tub
gniretne detrats I
ylivaeh detnurg eH ”.oG“
”?gab rehtona evah uoy oD“
”.etunim eno evah uoY“
.rood eht drawot dereggats eh dna
.llaw etisoppo eht no enohs nug a gnidloh enoemos fo eniltuo ehT
.ylkciuq knarhs tub regnol syawla saw enil ym os
.derrefsnart I hcum woh fo tnuoc tsol I ”.em tsurT
.sregnif sih deirrow eh dna
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,drow eno si pukcitS
teef sih ot tog ynnoK
tuo deruop stsev foorptellub dna smrofinu ecilop ni sevloW
.wodniw eht ta delley eH
,eloh eht hguorht tif ot egral ooT
.llaw eht tsniaga pu mih porp dna
kcab eht otni deirruh I  ”.ereh tiaW“
,tfel remotsuc tsal ym nehW
,roolf eht ot detniop I ”,woN“
.yawllah eht ni detegdif ynnoK
.retnuoc eht no sregnif sih demmurd dna woble na no denael ohw ,nooccar a
,lamina yerp a gnieB
,yaw eht no erom dna emoh ta stik ytnewt htiW
.sllib fo sluftsif hguorht dewehc redderhs eht sa degnirc ynnoK ”.ni gnimoc er’ew dna setunim ruof evah uoY
.ammoc a ton ,gab retfa doirep a evah dluohs uoY .tuo ti epyt
.revliS reganaM hcnarB si sihT .olleH“
.eerht ym dniheb enil ni llef dna denaorg
.hcum sa semit eerht diap eb dluohs stibbaR
,niaga ecnO .der ees em edam
.pu sdnah ruoy htiw tuo emoC
.edistuo pots a ot dehceercs srac ecilop lareveS
.llits yal tub eye na nepo dekcarc I
.ecneitap ruoy rof uoy knaht dna
.emit tsrif ym s’tI“
.sredluohs sih debbur dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,rood renni eht raen riahc s’reganam eht gnilloR
,roolf eht no stib eht gnilknirps
.yenom eht gnidih yb tuo erugif reven ll'yeht taht eramthgin gnitnuocca na ekam ot gniog era eW“
.enil eno rebmemer ot dah ylno uoY .enil enO“
”?tluav eht tuoba tahW
.em ta ti detniop dna nug a desiar eh ,tekcop sih otni gnihcaeR
.sexob tisoped ytefas ylno ,tluav eht ni yenom on s’erehT“
.enim naht gnitnioppasid erom saw reward s’ypO
”.devirra tsuj nav gib A“
,daeh sih desiar eh nehW
hteet sih dettirg eH ”?lla s’tahT“
wodniw sih fo tnorf ni sremotsuc ehT
.elbuort otni teg ot mih tnaw t’ndid I
.selgna prahs ni nezorf erew stnioj eht dna
.wodniw detnit eht tuo dekool eh sa delbmert eH
.nottub eht dehsup reve eno on ,sraey net nI
ecaf sih ot ti gnitteg
.snug rieht gniydaer yb detcaer sreciffo eht fo setteuohlis ehT
,mrof s'ypO revo gnippetS "?huH"
”.ebut citamuenp eht tuo meht wolb dna
.wodniw eht ni eloh eht hguorht ti dehsup dna
.ypO drawot deddon eH ”?reward sih tuoba tahW“
,tol gnikrap eht dnuora decar ecilop ehT
.dednuorrus ecalp eht evah eW
”.suovren elttil a m’I
mrof llits s’ypO ta delrans dna revo dekool
"?ereh tnuocca na evah uoy oD"
,smra sih otni drawkcab depmuj I sa
gab eht tuo dleh eH
,tsaf erew ew wenk enoyrevE
.teem sdne ekam ot stibbar rof elbissopmi saw tI
,ni semoc enoyna fI
”.setunim evif tog ev’uoY
wodniw s’ypO fo tnorf ni morf
.kcab ti dehsup I
.hguorht meht devohs I sa
.mra sih dettap I
.nottub taht gnihsup dessim reven tub
.ria eht ni swap sih htiw roolf eht no llits yal
”.tuo segatsoh eht gnidnes m’I
.ecnarusni efil eht tcelloc llits nac efiw ym ebyaM
erew sdnah yM ”.ni gnimoc er’ew dna setunim eerht tog ev’uoY“
.su fo eno neve rof hsac hguone ton s'erehT“
.ffo yap yllanif ot gniog saw ecitcarp fo sraey neT
.ereh ni srellet owt tog ev’I“
.depoord seye sih dna
".erif ruoy dloH .nem ,kcab yatS"
.gnilleps elam eht s'tahT"
.drac sih em dednah eH ".haeY"
,dnah eerf sih htiW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.ria eht dettap I ".gnilleps
.tnuocca s'ynnoK otni stnuocca modnar morf stnuoma llams fo srefsnart gninnur nageb I
.ebut citamuenp eht hguorht meht gnitoohs dna
.lanimret eht morf pu kool t’ndid tub daeh ym koohs I
.kcilc citsalp a htiw roolf eht no derettahc dna
.emit hcum ton s’tahT"
.yslap htiw enoemos yb nettirw fi sa elbadaernu erew srettel kcolb eht
,mus ydit a saw tI
.edis ot edis morf detrad seye sih erehw seloh ediw htiw ksam kcalb niht a yb neddih saw ytitnedi sih
ssalg etalp eht edistuo swodahs ehT
.swodniw tnorf eht no llef wodahs s’ypO
.ybbol eht hguorht gniog tuohtiw knab eht fo tuo teg ot yaw ysae on saw ereht tub ,nur evah dluow I
.shtoob rellet eht ot kcab deirruh I
.eton lacisum a tsomla saw syek eht fo gnikcilc ehT
.stekcop sih dettap eh sa yllacitarre gnuws nug ehT ”?gab tahW“
:yojne esaelP  .redneB ycatS
,sboj sserts wol krow ylno dluow smussopO kniht dluow uoY
.rae sih morf enohp eht dekrej eH ”.raed olleH…mU“
.etunim a snoitcasnart nezod a gniretne llits saw I tub ,derit gniworg
”.snioc era tfel si taht llA
.retteb teg dluow sgniht ecnahc on saw ereht
.mih rednu morf tuo deppils teef sih
.pleh emoc dluow eh thguoht I
,dnah eno htiw retupmoc eht gnikroW
”?ti toG .ecnalubma na llac ot spoc eht rof lley dna rood eht tuo em yrrac ,og yas I nehW
dewob daeh s’ynnoK ”?huH“ ”.truh
.dehcnub sworbeye sih dna deppid daeh siH
.teef sih dnuora tuo dellips snioc ,tsrub gab eht fo mottob eht nehW
.su detarapes taht ssalg eht ni eloh eht hguorht ti dehsup dna
erots tnuocsid a fo ogol eht htiw dessobme gab repap a tuo dellup eH
.redluohs sih dettap I .deddon eH
ecaf ym demraw thgilnuS  ”.yrroS“
htrof dna kcab degdod
.enod ev’uoy tahw kool woN“
.pets a togrof I dezilaer I litnu
.gab eht ni yenom eht lla tup ,syas tI
,mih ediseb roolf eht no tas
.srekoolno desufnoc tsap nar ew sa em dewollof dna
,reihsac eeniart dna mussopo eht ,ypO
snalp lareves pu demaerd I ,seow laicnanif nwo ym ta noitarepsed gniworg fo sraey net ym nI
.stsif sih dellab nooccar ehT ".pu
.hguorht hsup ot gniyrt eldnah eht otni daeh ym dekcams eH
.nooccar eht ta devaw dna wodniw eht no deppat I
.demrah eb t'now uoy dna og segatsoh eht teL
”.pukcits a si sihT
ydaer demees llA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ees I ?ti fo enoN
.ereh hcum ton s'erehT“
ti hctac ot deirt nooccar ehT
”.eybdooG .uoy knahT
.enohp eht derevoc eH
.delaid dna deddon ynnoK
.em ta nug eht koohs dna
,gnihceercs eht neewteb ni drow a teg ot gniyrT
”?gniknab enilno od uoy oD“
desiurb erew sregnif ym fo spit ehT
,noitcerid lareneg ym ni detniop nug eht gnipeeK ”.sknahT“
.noitisop otni ypO tsiwt ynnoK pleh ot revo deggoj I
.mra sih dehcnup I
.ksed s’reganam eht yb redderhs a s’erehT“
dehcnub sredluohs s’nooccar ehT
.seye sih depiw dna detrons eH ".siht
.emit txen retteb hcum od ll’uoY“
.gab eht otni kcab meht dehsup eh sa detnuoc dna
.ksam taht ffo ekat woN“
.tca ot egaruoc eht dah reven tub
.saw eh naht ereh gnieb ecilop eht tuoba reippah yna t’nsaw I
”?uoy pleh I yam woH
sdnah sih ni nug eht tuP
.dnah tfel ym htiw gnitirw yb ti esiugsid ot gniyrt saw I tub ,doog ytterp yllausu si pihsnamnep yM“
,roolf eht ot nwod pmal ksed eht gnilluP
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ecilop eht si sihT"
.pu teg ot gniyrt deppots nooccar ehT
.sllib gnirettulf eht gnisahc
.hguone eb lliw tI“ ".emit
.ni deggol llits saw lanimret sih ees ot dalg saw I
”.mia gnikat si eh ekil smra sih esiar dna
edarit eht derongi I
tol gnikrap eht fo kcab eht ta ecnef eht depmuj eW
dnah sih morf deppils nug ehT
.tnemeerga detareggaxe ni deddon I
.swodniw eht ta snug rieht delevel dna
.daor eht no llef eW .tsap dils dna
.srae nrot sih ffo deppils tsomla tah elygra demmirb-ediw sih
.daeh sih no ruf gninniht eht dehctarcs dna tah sih ffo koot eH
.daerd ot denrut tlef I ytip ehT
.thgir gnihtyna od t’nac I"
.gab repap eht otni snioc esoht llornU“
.retal nialpxe ll’I“ ”?yhW
”.edarap a tsuJ .raed gnihtoN“
roolf eht ffo meht tpews eh
.daeherof sih deppals eH
.esiar a em evag reven ,reganam s’knab eht ,revliS .rM ,sraey eseht lla retfA
.gab eht ni yenom eht tuP“
.rotaregirfer eht denepo dna
”.duola ti yas ro uoy htiw eton eht ekat tsuj dluoc uoy ,rettam taht roF
.yllacinortcele knab eht bor ot gniog er’eW
,noitcasnart tsal a retfA
.snoitcasnart erom wef a retne ot detnaw tub ,htob su rof hguone deretne dah I erus ytterp saw I
.rood tnorf eht ta derehtag dna snopaew rieht deidaer ecilop ehT
.enohp eht em evag yltnatculer eh
,ysub si redderhs eht elihW“ .stnuoma regral
.emit hcnul ym s’ti ,htiw uoy pleh nac I esle gnihton s’ereht fi woN
.eud emac tsuj taht eton mret-gnol a no krowrepap eht tuo llif ot eciton trohs hcus no knab eht otni emoc dnabsuh ruoy gnittel rof uoy knaht ot detnaw I
.lla ti dnif ot skeew meht ekat lliw tI
.stnemyap esuoh wef a dna drac tiderc eht ffo yap ot hguone detnaw ylno I
.sehtolc sih sa tuo nrow sa saw nooccar deggar eht ,pahc redlo nA
,hcinniM dieR yb ”egatsoH“
.yawa ti gnulf I sa enohp eht thguac eH
.nwardrevo saw tnuocca nwo yM
.reganam eht fo senot peed ,htooms eht detatimi dna
,gninnips ti gnidnes ti deppals tub
detautcnup erew ecnelis desselb fo sdnoces ehT
.retnuoc eht no gnihton saw erehT ”.yrruH
.denihw eh ”,neerg s’tI“ ”.doolB“
.efil ym ni tsaf os depyt reven ev’I
.edis ot edis morf dellol daeh siH
.A eht tuo tfel uoy dna
.ria eht ni sllib gnignilf
”.ereht ni gab a si erehT“
.lliw reven yeht ebyaM
dewollof saw roolf eht otno gnillips snioc fo gab eht fo dnuos ehT
,rotaderp rossel a mih dna
.taes eht fo egde eht no snioc fo gab eht decnalab I
,stnev ria eht otni meht gniffuts
.nwod dekcud swodahs ehT
.eye na dekcoc nooccar ehT “.yllacinortcele
enim ot txen htoob s'rellet eht morf hsarc A
.trihs ym ot detniop eH ”?rof taht s’tahW“
”.emit txen snoitcurtsni wollof ot yrt tsuJ .ton sseug ,haN“
”.oG .oG .oG“  .detiaw I dna
.truh s’eH .ecnalubma na llaC
.ecivres cilbup a sa shtaed ruo deweiv ecilop eht
.thgirpu dekrej liat s’nooccaR ehT
”?thgir ;gniddik er’uoY“ ".yenom
.ti fo tuo pans dluow eh epoh ni flah dna regna ni flah
,htaerb peed a gnikaT
,mottob eht derevoc sderdnuh fo lufdnah ehT
ylwols denrut eH
.ylwols daeh sih koohs eh dna
hcinniM dieR yb ”egatsoH“
.ssenhsiloof fo tnemom sih tegrof dna yawa klaw dluoc eh spahreP
,eton a esu tsum uoy fI“
.siht ta doog yrev ton er’uoY ,kooL“
.daeh sih koohs dna gab dnoces eht morf pu dekool rebbor ehT
.gninrom yadnoM ylrae pu dewohs ylno ecilop eht ,mrala eht ffo tes werc gninaelc eht revenehW
,ybbol eht ot dnuora emac I .nalp on tub
.ecnatsid rieht tpek tub ni ees ot gniyrt
,wolf eht mets ot detfihs eh sA
.wols syawla erew sgninrom yadseuT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,dnah dehctertstuo ym ot gnidnopseR
.draobyek eht revo welf sdnah yM ".eruS .eniF“
"?em pleh ll'uoY"
.thgiarts tniop t'ndid eye thgir sih sa yretsym a saw rof gnikool saw eh tahW
,snet ,seitnewt eht tub
,nooccar a rof ylkciuq dekrow eH
.teef sih ot mih dellup I
dah I naht ytiroines erom dah taht elttob puhctek eht ,rorroh ym oT
depmuls sredluohs siH
srosicni deppihc siH
.seye sih rednu tew werg ruf keehc siH
”.sdrocer cinortcele eht ni sekatsim llams fo sderdnuh rof gnikool eb t'now yeht ,elihwnaeM
,azzip toh yrev a tae ot gniyrt saw eh ekil enohp eht deldnah eh
.tsac yerg-nworb a ybbol s’knab eht evag wodniw detnit egral eht hguorht gnimoc nus noonretfa ehT
.gninrom yreve daeh ym ni erew sdrow emas esohT ".ecnarusni
nac eht ffo pot eht gnillup htiw delbmuf eh
.wodniw tnorf eht morf dehsinav swodahs eht dna
ecilop gnisruc dna snioc gnilgnij noillim a fo dnuos ehT
.spils lawardhtiw dna tisoped knalb eht htiw
”.txen ti steg rehto eht dna seid tibbar eht
mrof digir eht dils ynnoK
.toof ym rednu saw nottub mrala eht ,esneT
.ffits gniworg erew sdnah yM ”.llet nac I“
pils wardhtiw a dils nooccar ehT
.deneppah gnihton tub ,toof rednu dekcilc nottub ehT
.deggas nug eht gnidloh dnah ehT
.epacse on s'erehT" ,demoob eciov A
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
su otni dehsarc sredluob derevoc ruF
.maercs detrotsid a htiw
”?retteb ti od I dluoc woH ?ecitcarP“
”.dnilb-roloc era sevloW“
.daeh ym detlit dna pu dekool I
.elzzum gniyerg sih fo tuo dekeep
sllib eht fo emos ekaT
,efiw sih htiw ifics yrruf dna yrruf ,ifics setirw-oc ohw
.uoy htiw dneirf ruoy ekaT .no oG
”.og s’teL .pu teG“ .euc ruo saw
”.emit wohs s’ti nehT“
.smra sih dessorc eH
,eit kcalb dna trihs etihw
.denediw seye s’ynnoK
.yawa ti gnikrej dna
.retnuoc eht no sbmob eyd owt tes I ".gab
.edisni dehsad dna su revo depael sevlow gniniamer ehT .spop owt yb
.tah sih rednu deraeppasid sworbeye s’nooccar ehT
.seod ehs kniht I tub ,sllib eht syap efiw yM“
”?taht fo kniht I t’ndid yhW“
.rednerrus I“ .detuohs I
,egaruoc eht dna smelborp emas eht dah nooccar ehT
.pil sih tib rebbor ehT "?woH"
”.em deyaled uoY
.ecaf ym ni nug eht devaw dna denrut rebbor ehT
?em toohs yllaer eh dluoW
?srotaderp erew sreganam lla ti si yhW
.ytpme tsomla saw
”.ti tuoba kciuq eB .tnemyap esuoh a ekam dna drac tiderc eht ffo yap ot reh ksa dna reh llaC
,detcurtsni sa did ynnoK
.yenom eht lla pu dnirG
,ydob digir s’ypO dekcik I
”.ti daer t’nac I .yrroS“
,wol os gnuh daeh sih htiw
.pu thgil eht delgna I
,eno tsrif eht rof tpecxE
.tsehc ym nwod ti deraems I
.tisoped s'esuom a ni nioc naidanaC a gnidnif yb desuac saw sisotanaht fo kcatta tsal siH
?eton raey-evif-ytnewt rehtona otni revo llor ot tnaw uoy od yenom siht fo hcum woh ,woN .doog yrev ,hA“
”.ni gnimoc er’ew ro rednerrus ot setunim owt evah uoY“
,pmal eht gnitsiwT
.stibbar naht repaehc dekrow yeht tub
,dnoces tilps a roF .doots dna
.detniop dna dnuora repap eht denrut I
”.meht pord ot ton luferac eb tub
.htob su pleh ot gniog m'I"
.thgin yadnuS tsrif yreve demuucav yeht nehw werc gninaelc eht rof tpecxE
.regnol elihw elttil a gnisseug meht peek ot tog ev’eW“
.enohp eht revo dnah sih tup eh dna ria eht tuc eciov llirhs A ”– uoy dluoc tub
.roolf eht no noitisop gnittis a ni pu mih depporp dna
.elomacaug fo reniatnoc lluf a saw ereht ,yletanutroF
yaled eht rof yrroS“
.demrah eb ton lliw uoy dna segatsoh ruoy esaeleR
.detser ew erofeb elim a flah rof deggoj dna
.revo ti gnidnah dna tuo gab eht gnitfil erofeb roolf eht no stpiecer eht depmud dna
”.tib a decitcarp ev’uoy retfa niaga yrt dna emoh kcab og dluohs uoy ebyaM
,pot no eseht tuP“
.siht fo tuo htob su teg ll'I .pu evig t'noD"
.elims yldneirf a em evag dna ,em ot kcab denrut ,revo dekool eH
,dnuora ti gninrut dna gnitsiwT
roolf eht fo saera egral ssim ot deganam syawla selom ehT
,sgge eht tegrof t’now I .raed ,esruoc fO .seY“
”.hcnarb llams a er’eW .yrroS“
,ksed s’reganam eht yb ereht revo ypO gard ,ereh kcab teg“
”.hcaer nac uoy ynnarc yreve ni sparcs eht fo sdaw edih
”.noos emoh eb ll’I .raed ,ciffart eht s’tI“
.dednuorrus ecalp eht evah eW“
.ynnoK ot deddon I
saw sihT     ”?emit txeN“