– noitatnacni na derepsihw eH .dniw rof ngis
,nwo sih tsol dah eh esuaceb
,tsurt rieht dah ecilop eht ecnO
fo tros taht gniveihca
”?uoy ot emoc ll'eh kniht uoy oD
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.won sevlowerew ruof dah kraP lartneC
.nar emos ,tuo deirc emoS
”.su fo yna ot deneppah evah dluoc tI
.ecnanimod sehsilbatse tI“
– tseretni fo gnihtyna gniod t'nsaw eh hguoht
,sdnoces ytriht spahrep dah dna dniwnwod saw eH
edis sih dehctulc eH
.neercs aremac eht ta gnikool
,dliub emas ,riah kcalb fo kcohS
”espylacopA enO :dnuoF“ dna
,sbir eht ni dluoc eh  sa drah sa mih dekcik dah yob eht
”?uoy did ,mih truh t'ndid uoY“
”?bacixaT ,uoy htiw erutcip a teg ew naC“
,krap eht hguorht gniklaw rehtaf sih dna yob a fo rettahc enani eht draeh eh sa
.emit elpma saw hcihw
,ytingid fo snosaer rof strohs raew sevlowerew eht lla taht detadnam dah ytiC ehT
ksud gnirehtag eht otni
,sevlesmeht gnillortnoc fo elbapac yltcefrep erew yeht taht seitirohtua tnaveler eht ot detartsnomed dah yeht ecnO
,retaw rof ngiS
.deraeppasid ylevitceffe dna
.taews ni gnitaniram
.kcaP elttil rieht ni selamef on erew erehT .ruf tsniaga ruf
.pu flesmih dewoble naC hsarT
,yrt a ti evag llits sretropeR
.eb ot dedneterp eh yppup gnidnuob eht tib eno ton
.sgod toh s'yekuL no gnikcans
ta slleps tsac ylno yehT
.wol gniyats ,riovreseR eht fo gniknab eht gnola depol eH
.daeh sih koohs bacixaT
.tnardyH eriF dias
– dekcilc aremac eht sa tsuj edis sih ni niap prahs a saw erehT
.ni delwarc bacixaT dna
,enam sih hguorht swap sih nar eH
,redrob naidanaC eht raen skcaP eht fo eno morf tilps ylbaborp d'yeht tub
,egdirdoogneb@ egdirdooG neB yb ”goD toH“
.stsiruot detcartta dna srodnev eht rof ssenisub doog erew yehT
,mih tuoba lived lufrednow a saw erehT .yleguh gninnirg
.teef sih ot flesmih devaeh dna
,lla retfa ,sevlowerew erew yeht
.rehtona ro dnik eno fo sretah llA
,miws ot devol eH
rorrim eht ni kool lliw tcudorp ruoy ,won morf sraey eerhT
.elbmaR eht ni dnuora gnilbmuf yb
dehctiwt srae siH
yaw eht fo tuo devom emos elihw ,tnedicca ciffart a ta gnirats fi sa dehctaw srehtO
.ediw tib a denepo seye ,pu srae
,nettogrof flowerew eht
tnardyH eriF dna goD toH
ediw swap sih fo sregnif eht daerps ot devol
.aremac eht ta ylthgirb demaeb dna
,devil yeht erehw aedi on dah ecilop ehT
.tsew ,tsae ,htuos ,htron
.seert eht gnoma yawa neddih
.nwod looc ot riovreser eht ni maws bacixaT
.goD toH dias ”,em rof neetneveS“
,tneisnart erew yeht ,yllacinhcet
.ecaf sih gnikorts ,naC hsarT dias ”,dooG“
yks nepo eht sa tnatropmi sa t'nsaw ssenilnaelc tub
”?erutcip a rof uoy ksa eh diD ?deneppah tahW“
.tenretnI eht dnuora gnitaolf erew
,yad lufituaeb a saw tI .devaw goD toH
,goD toH dias ”?kcoR“
reteiuq saw ti esuaceb ,thgin
,suoregnad t'nerew
”.retal drac DS taht ta kool a teg yeht nehw kcohs a rof ni er'yehT“ .bacixaT dias
,snaej ffotuc derreferp bacixaT dna
,dekcilc aremac eht dna
”,nos ,ereh revo no emoC“
,noisivelet gninrom no deweivretni neeb htob dah
,thgie-esab ,emit siht ,srebmun
.yllacitsaisuhtne deggaw liat siH
.lla ta tnereffid gnihton
.tseretni decitcarp htiw semiT kroY weN s'yadretsey daer eH
.loohcs etarak fo dnik gnorw eht ni denrael tros a fo kcik gnittilps-draob ,esuohdnuor a
,meht fo espmilg a gnihctac fo sepoh eht ni kraP lartneC ot emac ohw
nwo rieht fo stsiruot gnitcartta dna
.gnibbe edis sih ni niap eht ,kcab sih no yal eH
.dlrow eht htiw thgir saw llA .deerga eH
– gnisirprus t'nsaw sihT
,nwolc a dna retsnom a neewteb ssorc a
”.ereht dnats uoy dna ,ereh tis ll'I
.mih ot ti dessot dna trac eht fo edis eht ni tnemtrapmoc a fo tuo god toh a dellup yekuL                 ”!yekuL ,yeH“
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,tenalpruF rof
.dnim sih dedavni regna on dna
”,tnempoleved lacisyhp sih ni gnola raf etiuq saw yob ehT“
,noisiv larehpirep sih ni gnidnats yob eht was bacixaT                 .daD dias
,tlep dna ruf sih ni retaw fo leef eht devol
.kcor eht morf nwod gnippoh ,bacixaT dias
swap sih ni teef s'bacixaT koot naC hsarT
”?uoy era flowerew hcihW“
”!flowerew eht ta kooL !flowerew a s'tI !kool ,daD ,yeH“
,ffo dezod bacixaT
,etelpmoc ligis ehT
emit eht saw woN
,snamuh rof efas dnoyeb
.kraP lartneC ni seert eht fo tuo gnidnuob emac sevlowerew eht fo eno nehw detcaer yeht woh no desab ytiC kroY weN ni stsiruot eht llet syawla dluoc uoY   egdirdooG neB yb
.thgilyad ni tuoba dna tuo saw eh nehw tol a tas goD toH
htaerb gnisnaelc ,peed a koot eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,etad yb-lles rieht tsap llew erew sgod toh ehT
,ecnatsni rof ,did yehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ria eht ni teef sih tup dna
,won htap eht nwod yawa gniklaw erew yehT
.htron eht fo stserof sseldne eht detnuah llits taht neM-laminA fo sebirT eht gnoma neve erar dna ecar namuh eht ot tsol gnol egaugnal a
”.esialam lleps-tsoP“
”?I t'ndid ,doog laer mih tog I
ycavirp dna dnim fo ecaep sih ot lufesu saw ti dna
”.sebirt sdnalredroB eht fo eno denioj dna ffo derednaw tsuj eris tsal yM .gnihcaet evol I“
,deddon bacixaT                 .daD dias
dias netfo dah goD toH
,tsettoh sti ta saw yad eht nehW
ecneconni deye-ediw gniyarteb mih fo sotohp taht wonk ot
,tca yloh a hsub a no gnieep deredisnoc taht msinagap gnigguh-eert
,steknalb fo elip rehto eht ni yal naC hsarT
ned eht fo tuo delwarc dna
.nus remmus eht ni eutats a ekil gninihs ydob gnilkraps sih
,sroloc fo krowhctap dliw a saw ruf siH
”,neetenin dah ev'I“
.niks sih rednu gnilwarc erew sgniht fi sa
nekorb eb ot elpmis oot saw ned rieht delaecnoc taht cigam eht tub
.setunim wef a ni senob rieht ot htob meht deppirts evah dluoc eh
.daD dellac ”!flowerew ,yeH“
.bacixaT dias ”,em rof neetfif sekam yob eht dnA“                 .naC hsarT dias
”?raf os ekam taht seod ynam woh oS“
,ssap mih tel dna
seye sih desolc eH
.syad neetriht dna ,shtnom ruof ,sraey evlewt saw eh ,sediseB
.bacixaT htiw nekat erutcip rieht evah dluoc tneilc sih dna eh fi deksa namssenisub ainrofilaC a ,yad taht retaL
.pu flesmih gniwoble ,goD toH dias
.tep bmud gib a sa suoregnad sa tuoba saw eH
.rae nrot a htiw flowerew ocilac a
,ti ta gnikool tuohtiw ligis eht no deppets yob ehT
”.sretsis dna srehtorb ruo otni seimene ruo gnikam yb deretslob era sknar ruO
,egdirdooG neB yb ”goD toH“ saw sihT
.tnardyH eriF dias
,tnelis dna ,elbisivni
nirg eguh a dennirg goD toH dna
!eruS“ ,dias ohw ,goD toH deksa lrig elttil eht dnA
– sretcarahc erom etorw eH
,retaw eht fo llems eht saw erehT
,morf erew yeht erehw enoyna dlot t'ndah yehT
,bir a nekorb d'eh kniht t'ndid eH
kcaP sih yb kraP lartneC ot dengissa neeb evah ton dluow eh ,revewoH
.detaler dekool yehT
,deffins eH .elgnairt a
”!goD toH s'ti ,yako s'ti ,yeH“
,etatspu morf meht htiw noigiler rieht gnirb
.eno em dekcos neht
,desiurb llits saw edis siH
,mih ot revo delddaw goD toH
,yawklaw eht no tlenk eH .gninnirg
snoitacilbuP laoG rof
.kcohs a etiuq reffus dna
.ylleb dna tsehc sih gnola evom selcsum gnikam
.gnillol eugnot ,ediw seye
.gniyrt fo kcal rof ton
.ecaf sih no kool eht ta kooL“
ehtirw ot demees ruf sih dna
.seye sih fo tuo riah sih depiw dna
,boj suoregnad a saw sihT
,lrig elttil eht dias
.evlewT ?neetrihT ?evlewT
sehsub eht fo tuo deppets bacixaT ,detarogivnI
.daor eht nwod sdray derdnuh a ligis eht yal I“
”.ycnetal retrohs a htiw dna ,syad enin dna ,shtnom ruof ,sraey evlewt ylno saw ohw yob a tsniaga tsac uoY
.snib eht hguorht gniggid ro
”!nos ,eno eciN“ ,dias daD sa tnemevap eht ot tuo wap rehto sih tup dna
.tib ynit eno metsysoce eht gnimrofsnart tuohtiw nattahnaM ni yawa werht snamuh taht doof eht no evil dluoc kcap eritne na taht
.hctaw ot derehtag dah sool-eikool wef a ,won yB
...nwod koohs eh dna ,hteet prahs ,gnol sih revo nar eugnot siH
,tsrif eht ni elcric dnoces a werd eH
?yob eht saw dlo woh ,timmad
,htap eht nwod sdray derdnuh A
”?gnignah ti s'woh ,goD toH ,yeH“
,ruoh eht ot nwod ega s'yob eht wenk eH
.noitarud tneced a lleps eht evag uoy tsael tA“
,yob eht dias ”,nam ,hO“
”,lleps eht rof gnuoy tib a si evlewt ,llitS“
”.llew snossel ym derebmemer I“
.meht hguorht retaw eht nur dna
.krap eht revo lla hsart pu dekcip sevlowerew eht ,sediseB
.yltneg meht degassam dna
,ylimaf gnidecer eht retfa derats eH
.riovreseR eht fo egde eht dekrow ohw rodnev trac-doof eht ,yekuL deirc
.moc.egdirdoog-neb.www no
.eb dluohs ti sa saw tahT
.decniw tnardyH eriF                 .bacixaT dias
,enihcam gnillik evitceffe ,tneiciffe na
– dnuorg eht no elcric egral a werd eh ,ylkciuQ
,desolc erew seye siH
,ti dedeen eh fi retaw renaelc teg dluoc eh
edis sih dehctulc bacixaT dna
.no deklaw yob ehT
.ycerces dna ycavirp rof sevil rieht ni moor ekam ot sniap nekat dah sdneirf eerht sih dna eh dna
elcric eht fo egde eht dnuorA
.llew etiuq ni gnilttes era meht fo ynam taht etacidni eniaM dna ,anaisiuoL ,nagihciM ,awoI morf stroper laitinI
eht s'tahW“ .sdiarb otni riah s'goD toH gniyt detrats eH
,eriuqca elpoep ynam taht setunim-neetfif dnuorgkcab
!goD toH ,yeH“ .elbmaR eht sdrawot yawhtap eht gnola dettort eh sa enoemos detuohs
.ytic gniticxe ,railimafnu na ni tsiruot a fo llems remmus eht dah dna
.meht gnitsegid elbuort on dah sevlowerew eht tub
ligis eht gniward tsuJ
.sucof etulosba rof
– roloc yna eb dluoc klahc ehT
.revo dna revo ,detnacni eH
.eulb ekil ot deneppah bacixaT
.klawedis eht no klahc eulb ni stigid cibarA-non
sliart gniklaw eht gnola gnicar
.dluow reve ro ,taht wenk namuh on hguoht
.bacixaT dias ”,os epoh I“
,llet dluoc eye yna sa raf sa elcric tcefrep a saw ti
.elihw a rof esiurb gib eno eb ot gniog saw eh tub
.steknalb eht ni mih ot txen yal eh sa luferac eb ot naC hsarT denraw eh dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
– snoitcerid eht ffo deggat eh dna
.sthgils deviecrep revo regna fo stif ot nevig saw eh fi
.ti gniward ot demotsucca-llew dnah decitcarp a htiw nward
,dias dna naC hsarT tsniaga delgguns eH
.ti dessot dna god toh rehtona tuo dellup yekuL .deraeppasid tI
.ecaf s'yob eht ni enilwaj s'nam dlo eht fo stnih
.shtnom rof ti gninnalp neeb ylsuoivbo d'eH
,mih hguorht pu degrus ecnagorra dna htuoY
”,noitcennoc gnorts a setaerc yllausu ecneloiV“
,gnitanicsaf saw eH
.otni sgniht gnittup rof stekcop dah yeht esuaceb
,llub a fo senob eht gnihsurc fo elbapac swaj dna hteet dna swalc
”.sdneirf fo elcric sih ni sutats htrow eb ll'tahT
.ylsuoipoc flesmih tew dna kool eno koot yob elttil A
.liart eht nwod ffo depol eh sa mih ot gniddon
.gnittis tuoba tneconni dna gninetaerht-non yrev gnihtemos saw erehT
,ebuTuoY no mih fo sruoh derdnuh a revo erew erehT
.ylisae og riap eht tel dluow bacixaT taht naem t'ndid sihT                 .debbe niap ehT
.dedne sehcraes eht
.seert eht fo repsihw eht saw ereht
,cilbup ni seippup gnilaeuqs ekil detca yeht sa hcum sA
,yot deffuts a ekil kool mih edam taht flesmih fo sotohp nees d'eH
aremac oediv a htiw gnola emoc dluow eno on dna
.yenom fo tol a edam evah dluoc eh ,sotohp rof degrahc d'eh fI
.ekoms eulb fo ffup tniaf a saw ereht ,delahxe eh nehW
nerdlihc devol eH
.etelpmoC .hsiniF .edulcnoC
,ytrof tuoba saw daD .dekool bacixaT
,gnitanicsaf saw eh wenk dna
.ees llits dluoc eh tub
”,bacixaT“                 .daD dias
,niatnuof eht ni gnihtab
.dnatsdnab eht morf detcudba gnieb saw ohw
”.mehcaD“ derepsihw dna
.bacixaT htiw derahs eh eno eht
,siht rof deniart d'eh ,llitS
.yawa meht esahc ot detnaw eno on ,esruoc fo ,woN
,gnitirw enacra dna tneicna werd eh
.dellortnocnu ,sselemoh
.dias eh ”,derit os m'I“
”!goD toH s'ti ,kool ,yeH“
.tnardyH eriF dias ”,ereh nevelE“
evitceffe erom erew yeht dna
.depsag bacixaT dna
.gnitarbelec htrow live suoyoj a
.ydaerla snoitamrofsnart ytnewt htiw ,owt ytxis sekam tahT“
dlihc a fo efil eht gnivas retfa oga shtnom emos srepap eht edam dah naC hsarT
.ananab a ekil mih gnippiznu fo elbapac dna ezis sih eciwt tsaeb a kcurts yob A
,ecarbme s'tnardyH eriF morf flesmih detacirtxe goD toH
sligis klahc rieht dna
”,toob gnikih a htiw yob dlo raey evlewT“
”?goD toH htiw nekat erutcip ym evah I nac ,ymmoM“
sehsub eht otni dednuob bacixaT
.mih ot txen ffo dezod naC hsarT dna
.daD dias ”,did erus uoY“
.tsom ta ,evlewt saw noS
.og meht dehctaw dna
.ycoidi dna ecnarongi fo eramthgin a
.seert gnirepsihw eht dna
,gnikool t'nsaw I litnu detiaW“ .deddon bacixaT
segalliv elbaturcsni dna dedulces wef a erew ereht erehw
.noitcerid dniw eht rof ngis a werd neht
,gniffins-htrae na
.sdneirf ym ,su htiw desaelp yrev era sretsaM ruO
.wenk eH .ruof-evlewT
,ned yzoc ,derettulc rieht ni rehto hcae tsniaga yal tnardyH eriF dna goD toH
,ecafrus eht ot mih ni cigam eht nward dah
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,eb ot derb saw eh rotaderp eht yleritne
kcab sih no llor dluow goD toH
.erehwyreve saw doof dna ,yad toh a
.kniht I ,sraey eerhT“                 ”?ycnetal
,ned eht fo htuom eht revo llef wodahs A
.srae eht neewteb elssut a rof nwod daeh sih dneb tsuj ro ,trac doof eht dnuora selcric tort
.klahc klawedis fo eceip a tuo dellup dna tekcop tew sih otni dehcaer eh
”goD toH“:yojne esaelP
.yppup tnaig a ekil dekool eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sevlowerew eht fo ned eht dnif ot detpmetta ,yllanoisacco ,dah ecilop ehT
sevlowerew eht taht cilbup eht erussa ot kciuq erew ecilop ehT
.kaeLeviL no meht tup dna
”alekA“ etorw ohw
,bacixaT dias ”,sey lleh ,hO“                 ”?tsaC uoy diD“
.doof emos dnif ot
.deilpmi taht tnemtnahcne dna yretsym eht lla htiw
”,taht ekil segami peek ot ekil snamuh emoS“
,riovreseR eht dna elbmaR eht dnuora emoh ta sevlesmeht edam yeht
.liart eht nwod ffo depol dna
.tnardyH eriF dias
.laeppa rieht fo trap saw gniht a hcus eveileb ot ton gnisoohc tub
,riovreseR eht ni tuoba gnilddap ,dnuora gniklaw
.krap eht revo lla erew
.dedracsid snamuh taht hsart eht no def gnipeek
si yrots s’yadot dna
,kcor a otno yllufecarg flesmih dellup dna decafrus eH
.ecaep dna teiuq ,mlac
,ssenllits ot dnim sih denepo dna
– naelc yrev t'nsaw retaw ehT
”.raed ,goD toH ksa dluohs uoy kniht I“ ,dias ymmoM dna
,ti htiw elppir dna
”.lufrewop yrev saw noitcennoc ehT
,kcans a rof slezterp tfos gnitabed dna renroc eht dnuora gnimoc rehtaf sih dna yob eht
,desolc seye sih htiw tnemom A
;ssenisub rof doog saw eh esuaceb goD toH dekil yekuL
.hgih oot raf erew sekats eht dna
,egnahc yna fo ngis on saw erehT
,decitonnu meht dessap eh sa
”,lleps eht rof erutcip eht deniard t'ndah I fi ,dluow ti ,lleW“
”!kool a ekaT“ .yob eht htiw evif-hgih a deppals dna
,mih ot txen doots lrig elttil ehT
.swaj lufrewop sih neewteb ti thguac dna pu depael goD toH