?nrocs fo laed taerg a dnA selacs ni dalC ?nrober I mA
.seirots setirw dna semag sekam ohw
egnahc sesuac tnemevom lliT
erif eht rof leuF
traeh ruoy ton nedraH
tsur ot tnaem senob dnA
tsud ot tsuD sehsa ot sehsA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
!oeD sislecxE nI  !airolG !airolG
nik ym nepo derhs oT swalc eht em tnarG
eman sih raeh uoy nehW
niks ym nedrah dnA selacs ym tuo worg ll'I oS
.egap yrruFoS sih no dnuof eb nac smeop sih fo eroM
egnahc sesuac tnemevom lliT
traeh ruoy ton nedraH
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
fo noitcarf a neve teg mrah tsom eht
ksa uoy od netfo woH
”?ksA uoY oD netfO woH“   yojne esaelP
mlasP a ni tif t'noW yrgna gnitteg esoppus I
?mlac ylbatrofmoc oS yats I nac woH
ecno rof deifitsuJ leef uoy dibrof doG
esuac ohw elpoep taht
.irikenen.www no
tirips eht yb devoM
mrywkooB irikeneN yb meop a
hsa taht morf dnA
.nwo sih fo seirots emos etirw ot emit sekam eh
tsud ot tsuD sehsa ot sehsA
ecno rof deifitsuJ leef uoy dibrof doG
evorg rieht nI slegna htiw enid oT evoba pU
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT .teop eht yb daer ,mrywkooB irikeneN yb ”?ksA uoY oD netfO woH“ saw sihT
tirips eht yb devoM
,skoob daeR-oT fo draoh sih morf gnidaer ton s’eh nehW
em tfil ot sgniW
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
eman sih raeh uoy nehW
.teop eht yb daeR  .moc.irikenen.www
!oeD sislecxE nI  !airolG !airolG
?flesruoy evig uoy
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb si meop s’yadoT dna
doG fo htarw eht
tsur ot tnaem senob dnA erif eht rof leuF