enog saw eh nehW
”?galf edirP eht htiw gnorw
,yppah elpoep ekam ot gnol os rof t’nsaw I enoemos eb ot gniyrt neeb d’I dnA
.gnihtemos od ot detnaw
.noitartsurf ni daeh ym koohs dna pil ym tib
.seliM htiw derahs I eno eht morf raf oot ton
tahW“	            .mih morf yawa emit dneps ot ecnahc a dah I nehw eciton t’ndid I taht sgnihT
woH“	            .kaerb remmus erofeb shtnom wef a etad ot detrats
gnihtemos yas ot elba eb ll’I
I	            .saw toggaf a tahw gninrael rebmemer I neht
.ynnaD saw eman siH
.diova ot drah os dekrow ev’I taht snoitatnorfnoc fo taerht gnimool ,gninrub sihT
mih ot riaf ton s’tI
.tsrif ta ynnuf os demees tI
.emag oediv a gniyalp dellik tog eh nehw ro
,ereht tas tsuj eh tuB
,reciffo na won tsuj saw eh esuaceb saw ti ebyaM
,elamef dna elam
.semit eht fo tol a tceffe rof toohs ot gniyrt tsuj saw eh ekil demees ti rebmemer I
.ti nruter ot mees t’nac I tub
.roivaheb sih htiw seussi
.seliM htiw noitceffa ni detseretni ssel elttil a flesym dnuof I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
I	            .sraet ym lortnoc ot deirt I sa em guh dluoc ehs os reh ot resolc em dellup dna denworf ehS
”!hctib gnikcuf a
I	            ?gniod I ma lleh eht tahW
,sevlesruo noitanimircsid derudne gnivah ,lativ s’tI
neeb osla s’eh tub
gnihtemos yas ot ,htuom ym nepo ot deirt
,neht dna won setad wef a teg ot deganam I ,redlo tog I
htiw sevlesmeht eb tsuj dluoc yeht enoemos dah yeht ekil tlef ti
.esle gnihtyna yas ot mih rof gnitiaw fi sa ,kool a nooccar eht tohs seliM
,elpmaxe na dna
,nem ot detcartta ylralucitrap flesym dnif t’ndid I ,redlo tog I
.ezeeuqs dna eldnah eht barg I
s’tahW“	            .taht ekil gnivaheb saw eh nehw
.htiw revo lla siht teg dna rood taht nepo ot tnaw I
,ta dekool erew senioreh eht taht yaw taht ni ta dekool eb ot detnaw I
I	            .dik a tsuj llits saw I nehw ib saw I wenk
.noitseuq ni reven saw emit eht fo tser eht detca eh yaw eht dnA
”.ereh eb ot evah t’nod uoy
tnemtrapa reh ni tuo gnignah erew eW
”?ohW“	            .pal ym ni daeh sih ,delley seliM
.ti htiw yako dna gnidnatsrednu
nekat ev’I nosaer a s’erehT
neht thgir pihsnoitaler ruo ni sserts eht ot taht detubirtta
tahW“	            .enohp sih no gnihtemos gnidaer saw eh dna noonretfa llaf a no dnop eht yb tuo gnignah erew ew emit taht saw ereht
.od ot dah I tahw od ot denedlobme
.sih otni gnirob seye reh ,dias haraS
.taht ekil mih no kcab ym nrut tsuj t’ndluoc I
,mih htiw eugra ot gniyrt esnes on saw ereht
d’I	            .thgir saw ehs esuaceb
ereh detpecca si ytinummoc reeuq eht fo trap rieht taht meht wohs ot deen ew
fO	            .neht ecnis revo dna revo ot kcab gnimoc neeb ev’I noitseuq eht saw
.galf wen a ekam ot deen yeht kniht elpoep od yhW
,neht naelc emoc evah dluoc I semit fo snezod eht fo yna rO .ti saw taht
,emoclew ton er’uoy fi dna ,ecaps ruo si sihT
dah taht drow a saw tI
emos dnuof I taht mih llet d’I nehw tespu teg t’ndluow eh os ylluferac stnemmoc ym ecnad ot gnivah fo derit os saw I .derit saw I
dnA	            .tliub ev’I gnihtyreve niur dna
I	            ”.tesolc eht ni llits er’uoY
,nemow dna nem gnitad rof rail a enoemos llac dna euqitirc dluow eh emit hcae tuo dewolloh
.enoemos yb detpecca leef dna enoemos yb devol eb ot detnaw tsuj I
.em ot netsil ot dah eH
,yleerf em dnuora elpoep dna flesym ot timda nac I erehw erutuf eht
.erats tsuj dna riah sih htiw gniyalp mih ees dluow I .fo dnik
”?naem uoy od
.flesym tcidartnoc ot gnihtyna yas ot tnaw t’ndid I
eht fo emos eciton ot detrats I nehw saw tahT
”,yaw taht ti sees enoyreve toN“
tahW“	            .daeh ym deddon
.yag gnieb naht tnereffid si naibsel gnieb ro snart gnieB“
.evol ni eb ot ydaer os saw I tub ,ffuts sdik laer
,ton ro gnikool-doog saw enoemos kniht ot gnihtyna ekil leef yllaer t’ndid tI
.syug dekil I dezilaer I taht 51 dnuora saw I nehw retal sraey elpuoc a saw
eW	            .dluoc yeht dias yeht ekil mih htiw tuo gnah ot elba t’nerew elpoep nehw yllanosrep noitcejer koot dna
.seye sih gnillor ,dias seliM ”,revetahW“
.enoemos dah esle enoyreve
,dnaherofeb shtnom wef
yeH“	            .yas ot egaruoc eht em sevig taht
.tsrif ta ssa na fo dnik saw flow
.lla ta ereht t’nsaw xe ym htiw tlef I tahw
eW	            .ykcor yrev saw
.dik a saw I ecnis evol ni eb ot detnaw I taht wenk tsuj I
.rehto hcae ta kool ysaenu na derahs haraS dna nayR .dias seliM
,driew tlef ti em dlot uoY
.meht htiw eb ot detnaw I
seliM nwonk ev’uoy naht regnol dneirf ruoy neeb ev’I tub
,haraS ,ecaps nwo ruoy tnaw uoy fI“ ”.democlew
.hguorht og dluoc loohcs eht ta sdik reeuq rehto tahw truh dluoc taht gnihtemos yas ot tnaw t’ndid I
,sraey rof noitasrevnoc siht evah ot gnitnaw neeb ev’I
t’ndid llits ti tuB
.seliM ta gnikool neve ton
tuB	            .em ot pu dekool yeht hcum woh em llet ASG eht ni namssalcrednu
,noitasrevnoc eht fo hcum rebmemer t’nod I tub
dnA	            .yag tub gnihtyna m’I kniht lliw enoemos deirrow ro ,suoicsnoc-fles leef ton dna
,ytiradilos si edirP fo esoprup eht fo traP
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ni dekcik neeb dah tsehc ym ekil
”.ssenisub ot kcaB“
I	            ”.tnaem uoy tahw wonk ot tnaw tsuj I
tsuj I tuB .esnet tlef tI
,did eh emit yreve dna etavirp ni meht delttileb eH
.sraey rof eno neeb dah seliM dna
.ti fo yna no reh thgif ot
,rehtegot emit rieht lla gnidneps syob ynroh owt llew
.daeh ym ni deniargni gnieb morf drow taht pots t’ndid tI
,daeh reh deddon haraS	            ”.ssorg fo tros
,seoreh eht eb ot tnaw t’ndid I
dnA	            .taht detnaw syawla I
!em ot netsil dluow eh
eH“	            .neht kcab hguone netfo od dluow eh sekoj fo dnik eht saw ti tub ,saw ti tahw rebmemer neve t’nod I
,haeY“	            .haraS dlot I ”,ti teg annog ton
!taerg tlef ti dnA
gnorw s’tahw
aibohpiB fo ssensuoidisni eht tuoba
tahW“	            .noitseuq taht deppop ehs nehw rehtegot seivom rorroh dab gnihctaw erew ew dna thgin eht rof enog saw etammoor reH
”.tuoba klat dluohs ew gnihtemos s’erehT
ohw ediced ot gniyrt eb ot demees eh tub
,eurt erew taht sgniht yas d’eH
.flesym gnisserpxe elbatrofmoc erom tog I sa otni worg ot flesym dewolla I ohw s’tI
,hcamots ym ni tsiwt tip eht gnileef
,elbaniatsus t’nsaw tI
,rehto hcae detah ohw elpoep owt neewteb kcuts pu dedne I dna sgniteem ot gnimoc deppots d’ehS
.elpoep yaG rof secaps ni democlew tsom eht yltcaxe t’nerew yeht ,taht erofeB
mih dnuora gnieb segde hguor eht fo emos dehtooms uoY .edur
,yag saw I dias I taht nialpxe naht mih ot eil ot renaelc tlef tI
.teem nac seye ruo dna
,hguone eurt tlef ro
,ybigreK yb ”tuO snaP ti woH“ saw sihT
ksa yeht nehw yltsenoh rewsna ot elba eb ll’I ebyam
”’.ti pleh t’nac ehS .syug dna
.ti detpecca fo tros tsuj I
,won sraey elpuoc a rof saw I ohw fo noitpircsed yako na ekil tlef
.rehtnap emit-lluf dna ,retirw emit-trap a s’ohw ,ybigreK yb ”tuO snaP ti woH“ si yrots s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
erew stnerap siH
.denetsil I erom eht ,deklat haraS erom ehT	            ”.rehtie
,tneuqerfni os saw ti tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.seliM ,si laed gib eht tahw ees t’nod I“
.noitanimircsid emas eht tsniaga seilla ruo ,ylimaf ruo ,su ediseb dnats ohw esoht tsniaga etanimircsid ot gninrael diova ew taht
,sretcarahc lanoitcif htiw daeh ym ni seirots citnamor elttil ekaf tuo tca d’I
sA	            .toggaf a gnieb fo snoitatonnoc wenk I tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,doom taht ni saw seliM
ekil tlef syawla ti dna hguor saw loohcS
I	            .ti dezilamron d’I
,semit ynam os noitartsurf ym fo ecruos eht htiw gniliec eht ta gnirats ,deb ot enog d’I
,seliM ot gniyl neeb d’I
tI	            .taht dah reven I dna
,em ta dekool dna rood eht ta deppots ehS
.haraS rof pu kcits t’ndid eh tub
tI	            .ykcor saw tI	            ?eniM
?gnikam saw ehs tniop eht no dnuorg reh gnidnats rof
.taht gnitaicerppa tsuj dna evitcartta saw ohw enoemos gniees flesym dnif dluoc I tub
.esrow tlef tsuj I
.rehtegot emit fo tol a tneps ew ,no neht morF
.gnitad detrats I ohw saw siht ekil leef t’ndid tI
.taht ssapmocne t’nseod galf edirP eht dnA
,wonk t’nod I	            …leef
;dneirfyob sih saw I
tlef I .eromyna ti od ot tnaw t’ndid I taht
.gnol os rof mih htiw neeb d’I
,eliv ylluf tlef reven stnemmoc ehT
,oot og ot detnaw eh ekil demees eH
I“	            ”?naem uoy od tahW“
,ssenippah nwo ruoy gnigatobas ekil sleef
.doohnosrep reeuq fo snoisserpxe tnereffid eht lla neewteb
.dias haraS dneirf ym ”,elohssa na
,llah eht gnicap ot em del
,won ydnert s’ti esuaceb reeuq eb ot stnaw ehS
.oot em raen secalp ta gnikool saw eh em dlot eh nehw
ehT“	            .raey roineS ruo fo gniteem ’sreciffo ASG tsrif eht gnirud dias eH
.gnitad nageb ew nehw mih tuoba denrael I sgniht tsrif eht fo eno saw taht
.ecaps reeuq eht fo renroc yreve morf sgalf elttil htiw
.flesym ot gniyl neeb
,enod tsuj d’eh tahW .gnorw saw tI
.mih tuoba dah eh ytilibarenluv laer a saw erehT
t’ndah ti tub ,noitpircsed tpa na tlef tI .egelloc deretne tsrif I nehw thgir tlef yaG
.nemow rof noitcartta ym dih I
.spukooh rof eno eb ton yam I taht redisnoc neve t’ndid I ,emit eht tA .ffo
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
eil ot em rof reisae saw ti tuB	            .em rof gnitimil
.seliM ,snaibseL yb fo erac nekat erew sisirc sDIA eht gnirud nem yaG
,pohs eeffoc a ta enoemos dnif nac I
.flesruoy ot riaf ton s’tahT
.thguac tog ew elbativeni saw ti
…yleritne demees reven ev’uoy esuaceb ,gnirednow tsuj m’I
dedne gniteem eht nehw esucxe emos edam I
”!haeY“	            .ruf s’rehtnap eht fo krad eht morf tuo gninihs thgil nedlog ,deworran seye reH
dna etad dluoc I .sega
.tnemtrapa ruo fo edistuo llah eht ecap dna noitartsurf ni gnitnurg
ebyaM	            ?sraey esoht lla rof gniod neeb d’I tahw taht t’nsi tub
ib flesym llac ot gniyrt naht
nrop dnuora gnikaens flesym dnuof I
.gniwollof etiuq ton ,deknilb
,dekil eb ot detnaw yletarepsed eH
.flesruoy fo strap edih ot evah ot uoy tnaw t’nod tsuj I
,ylwols gniklat detrats eW
s’eH“	            ”?taht ekil tihs gniyas s’eh dna ASG eht rof reciffo na eb ot gninnur s’eh ,ekiL .yako t’nera
.nialpxe ot drah saw ti
?siht ekil gnivil esuaceB
,dna ,tol a dessik eW
.troppus rof dnuora dekool eh sa desiar erew selkcah siH .depirg seliM
pu emoc dluow ti nehw yag flesym dellac I ,sgniteem ASG ot tnew I ,kcapkcab ym no nip edirp a dah I
ehT	            .saw I ohw gnieb dna
”,enoyreve fo gnitpecca si galf edirP ehT
mih thgif dna yrt ot ygrene eht evah t’ndid I
.yawa deklaw dna pu doots haraS
,erutuf eht fo thguoht eht s’ti tuB
I	            .swalc enilef reh htiw stned elbaezis gnikam dna puc citsalp reh gnihctulc ,depirg ehs
hcihW	            .flesym ot riaf t’nsaw ti dna
.evitcartta namow
?gnilf a tsuj saw ti esuaceb ti ekil t’ndid uoy
.tniop sih dnatsrednu I dnamed ot gninrub seye
,brab yreve ,tnemmoc yreve
ti pots ot gnihtyna yas t’ndid I emit yreve
tsuj sekoj fo sdnik esoht ,yltsenoH“	            .dias I
,ti ebircsed ot woh wonk t’ndid I
,sdrawretfA“	            …saw ti tuoba gnihtemos yas ot gnitteg yllanif dna
taht gnihtemos od ot ysae ton s’tI
ekil evah dluoc eW“
.rehtegot emit erom tneps ew sa rehto hcae wonk ot teg ot detrats ew
.su rof tuo krow dluow ti taht tbuod ot nageb I
sA	            .gniyduts ot kcab tnew dna nwod tuhs tsuj I ,daetsnI
sA	            .ylevitcelloc kniht lla dluow ew tahw s’taht ekil tlef tsuj ti
.em t’nsaw ti
!ecno ta htob semitemos
t’ndid I
.ti evah nac uoy naht
.detirips-naem dna ,sselerac tsuj
thgir eht si siht wonk I taht hguone tsuj
,gniklat trats ew sa
m’I“	            .si noitatneiro ym tahw
.ekil eb ot ebircsa ot desoppus saw I taht swohs VT dna seivom eht ni seoreh eht ot nward flesym dnuof
?nwod tis uoy nac ,ebab
.loop eht ta tem I nexiv ytterp
,em ta derats seliM
.gnorw tlef taht mih fo noisrev a saw sihT
.eussit a htiw skeehc ym ta dettab haraS litnu gniyrc saw I ezilaer neve t’ndid
.neppah lliw tahw fo diarfa oot m’I esuaceb flesmih rof pu kcits neve t’nac ohw drawoc a m’I
.dias haraS ”.oot
,niagA“	            ”.etuc eb yllaer dluoc tahT !naP ,ecA ,snarT
.ereh eb ot evah t’nod uoY
.ti od ot evah I wonk I
,dessik ew emit tsrif
.saw reeuq gnieb tahw dna
,taht ekil dleh gnieb denigami I nehw thgir tlef tsuj tI
.gnihton saw ti ekil yllausac os ti gniyas rehtorb redlo ym rebmemer
.eb ot desoppus erew sgniht yaw eht saw siht ekil tlef tI
,eugnot ym no eid ot demees sdrow eht tub
,bulc eht fo tuo reciffo na gnikcik
,ytitnedi redneg rieht fo sseldrager ,ytrilf
”,drah oot seirt yllaer
,era uoy tahw ro ohw uoy llet ot ecalp ym ton
.ot mees t’ndid srehto taht mih fo trap eht ees osla dluoc I tuB
,yrots ym mih dlot I	            .t’ndid I tub
yerbuA“	            .koobtxet ym morf pu gnikool ,deksa I
.elihw a rof enola eb ot tnew dna
,moor mrod derahs ruo ni seliM gniees
gnileef em tfel tsuj tI
nehW	            ”!dnim reh pu ekam tsuj dna gnidneterp pots ot sdeen ehS
.drawoc a m’I	            .ekoj roop yreve
.loohcs fo edistuo rehtegot emit gnidneps su htiw gniunitnoc dna
s’tI“	            .kcab gnihtemos gnidloh er’uoy ekil mees uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
noitulos doog a sa taht redisnoc ot em rof elbatrofmoc erom saw tI ?yltsenoh dnA
diD“	            .ezeeuqs evitroppus a gnivig dna enim hguorht sregnif reh gnical rehtnap eht
.sboj rof gnikool dna loohcs fo sserts morf secnavda ym gniffuber mih fo derit saw I ro
.retal ro renoos neppah dluow ti wenk I
…denoows I dna riah gnizama htiw naitamlaD etuc siht saw eH
,ti od ot mih evord tahw wonk t’nod I
ni sdrow reh koot I
,xe ruoy htiw noitcennoc peed taht dah uoY
.secalp tnereffid ot gnidaeh eb dluow I dna eh taht raelc erom dna erom emaceb ti
,moc tod rettiwT morf ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daeR  .aibohpnaP dna
.neht thgir detnaw I tahw t’nsaw ti ekil tlef tsuj ti tub
.yag flesym dellac I
.nemow sdrawot erised tlef llits tub
eht lla leef em ekam yltcaxe t’nseod galf edirP eht oS
.mih morf loohcs ot gnimoc erofeb pukooh eht dih I
bonk rood eht rof hcaer I	            .od ot gniht
I ohw ees dna erolpxe ot modeerf eht saw tI .efas tlef I dna
sseug I tub …retteb s’eh dna
.pu kaerb ot ton dediced I oS
,taht tuoba gnikniht
!elpoep fo tuo esnopser a tog taht drow wen a saw ereH
.ti ot egde na fo tib a htiw syawla tub
.depoord srae sih ,ereht tas nayR
.mih dnuora edih uoy naem I“	            .deksa I
,daor eht nwod yad eno
.ffuts sih pu kcap ot gnitrats
;daor taht nwod raf os nettog d’I
.mih fo edis taht fo erom dna erom was I ,no tnew emit
.em werht tnemmoc tahT	            .em dlot ehs
tsuj sa ecneirepxe ym dezilanoitar I
eW	            .hturt eht nialpxe ot yrt naht
woh rebmemer tsuj I
,ti dekil llits I
.nem snart tuoba ekoj emos dlot tsuj dah seliM
.yag uoy sllac seliM nehw yppah
ti gnimaercs morf mih pots ot hcum od t’ndid ti tub
.saw I ohw saw taht dna
ekoj rehtona ekam d’eh emit hcae rekcis dna rekcis leef em gnikam
,enog yllaer reven saw tI
”?yag erew uoy wonk uoy did
”tuO snaP ti woH“   :yojne esaelP
”,mih dnuora flesruoy eb ot teg neve t’nod uoY“
ehT	            .mih rof sgnileef dah I dezilaer I erofeb gnol t’nsaw tI
,mih htiw od ot gnihton detnaw I
,od ot tahw wonk t’ndid I
.yag flesym gnillac tpek I tub
dna yrt ot daetsni galf MLM eht tpoda ot detrats neve evah nem yag emos yhw s’taht ,lleH
,loohcs ot gnimoc erofeb lrig a htiw erew uoy em dlot uoY“	            .taht toN	            .…ton
.erac dna erised fo xim a htiw nees eb ot
,egelloc otni
.syug etad llits nac ehs os nepo rood eht gnivael s’ehs tub
.seliM htiw noitcennoc taht dah uoy
.mih htiw gniyats eb ot gniog saw I taht gniraeh ekil t’ndid haraS .no tnew llits I
.ytilauxes ym fo wolf eht ot bbe na saw ti tub
,ti debircsed eh yaw eht tuB
.esahc tuolc ot gniyrt tsuj s’ehS“	            .dias I
.nosaer a rof gnol os rof noitasrevnoc siht ffo tup
!suolucidir tsuj s’tahT“
.tif dluoc wenk reven I eceip elzzup a saw tI .tlef ti doog
…leef t’ndid I .doog leef
.raey roinuj rehtegot demoor neve dna ,egelloc tuohguorht gnitad tpek
.erofeb seliM detnorfnoc reven ev’I nosaer a s’erehT
,gnihtyna yas ot yrt neve t’ndid I
gnioG	            .sdrawretfa driew gnileef saw I yhw saw taht ,yag gnieb
,nepo ti llup dna
pu gnittel thgiew eht
.nap ro ,ib sevlesmeht gnillac ro
oot tlef llits yaG
…tlef I taht ylno
.mih diova ot tseb ym enod d’I
.thgir leef t’ndid sihT
?ekil taht saw
.seguag rae wobniar htiw nooccar a ,dias nayR
.mih gnivol sraey 2 tneps dah I .mih devol I
.mih rof ti dezitinas I tub
,dneirf tseb a ro rentrap a eb ti rehtehW
.dnuora elpoep reeuq rehto evah ot gnizama tlef tI
htuom ym nepo ot evah I ,emit s’tI
…tlef ti tub ti deyojne I
,sreltna ym barg dna kcab llup I nehT
.bonkrood ssarb detned eht ni noitcelfer ym ta erats I                ybigreK yb
.moc tod rettiwT morf ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer
yrtemonogirT ni tuo rehto hcae gnipleh htiw gnitrats
slrig htiw evol ni sllaf‘ ehs taht gniyas s’ehs naem
rof flesym fo edisni dleh d’I taht snoitasrevnoc eseht evah ot eerf ylneddus saw I
.nepo tfel erew sbat tahw tuoba luferac eb dna netfo yrotsih gnisworb ym raelc ot dah I
,ylwolS	            .rehtegot seitrap dna sgniteem emas eht ta pu dedne ew os sdneirf lautum fo tol a dah ew tub
.daeh ym deddon dna denetsil tsuj I
”.naem yeht edirp fo dnik tahw yfiralc
siht htiw remmus taht gnilf a gnivah pu dedne I dna egelloc erofeb pu gnikaerb pu dedne
.hcti sdap wap ym leef nac I
,yppah seliM ekam ot
.ylraed devol I mohw fo htob
,yag gnieb fo tpecnoc eht wonk neve t’ndid I
.pu gnikaerb redisnoc ot em rof naht
,detnaw I tahw ekil tlef I
,nossel tcejbo na tneserp ew oS
,egelloc retfa snalp tuoba klat ot detrats ew sa tuB
dah I nehw yllaicepsE
,rethgil sleef tsehc ym
.0102 ecnis sdrapoel dna shateehc neewteb ecnereffid eht gninialpxe dna krow yrruf gnitirw neeb s’eH
.tuo kcab gnimrots erofeb tnemom a rof gnisuap
.emit eht lla ti gnipporD
ev’I	            .nur ot tnaw I	            …tey
,uoy rof doog neeb s’eh wonk I dna
,trapa raf os rehtegot evah dluoc ew erutuf eht tuoba gnikniht trats dluohs ew taht mih gnillet no dennalp dah I
.esnefed fo dnik yna tnuom neve ot em rof redrah emaceb ti tuB
,mih htiw tsenoh eb ot semit eht lla
.pu gnitca morf mih tpek gnihtemos tub
.eugra ot enoyna rof moor evael t’ndid ti
putes NU elttil a
,stneduts wen emoclew ot si riaf erutluc
em sees eh nehw selims eH
I	            ”.won nemow otni s’ehs taht yas ot gniyrt s’ehS !azalP
nevE	            .yas ll’I ”,nap
,ereht tas tsuj I ,daetsni tuB
dneirfyob ym fo evol ym neewteb raw a ni senil ymene neewteb deppart
.gnol os rof enoyreve ot gniyl neeb d’I
.stonk otni tsiwt dluow hcamots ym semitemos taht suollac os eb dluow eh hguoht nevE
ehT	            .seliM tem I nehT	            .saw
yag flesym llac ot reisae tlef tsuj ti
,llabtoof ni yalp dab a dah enoemos nehw emit eht lla
”,ffo mih llet dluow enoemos hsiw tsuj I
.nemow ni detseretni tlef ylerar os I nehw
,tol a siht tuoba gnikniht neeb d’I
.seliM htiw noitasrevnoc eht gnivah trats ot sevren eht pu gnikrow
.ti rof dehca traeh yM
.ytpme tlef I .thgir
,tnemom taht ni mih fo derob saw I ekil tlef tsuj I ebyam
.evisulcni tsom eht neeb syawla ton s’tI“ .denworf nayR
.gnihtyna dias eh fi em htiw tespu eb d’eh wenk I dnA .nrop thgiarts—
,ti pots ot deirt stnerap ruO !rewop
rO	            .gnihton dias I dna
”?galf edirP eht htiw
,ti yb deroolf tlef I
I	            .deksa haraS ”?thgir
ytilanosrep siht tuo leef
…uoy ebyam taht kniht reve uoy
,od ot tahw tuoba deklat ew wonk