.aes eht revo gniylf erew eW
,noitazilivic keerG a yllaer saw
.rehtona dna ,rehtona deirt I
dluoc uoy gnihton ylniatrec dna ,flesym fo erac ekat ot woh wenk ylerab I“
dellac era ffuts elbixelf fo spirts gnol otno gnitirw fo snoitcelloC
nehctik eht otni kcab nar tsrif peelsa em dnuof ohw yob nehctik ehT
.em hcaet ot nageb dna
.dnuora eb ot demees eno oN
,gninaem sih dootsrednu yldrah I
.od ylerar yeht tub ,dnoces yna ta revo llaf ot dnuob era yeht kniht uoy semitemos
.sueZ fo noitcidsiruj eht edistuo dna
.rerar meht deredner tsuj dah I dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT no ereh thgir ro
,elbbin a deirt I .ytsat
.sipareS dog eht ot elpmet taerg a sa llew sa
”,elttil ,meht eta I esuaceb ton
.gnineve eht fo noitseuq lanigiro sih ot gninruter ,deksa beZ
,tcelletni na etiuq saw I taht decnivnoc ,sebircs eht fo eno ,taht retfA“
”.gninrom taht nedrag eht ni em was yeht sa noos sa noitcetorp rieht rednu em koot
,saes eht ssorca morf ecnerefretni ot yldnik ekat t’nod sdog naitpygE ehT
,srednow fo tsetaerg taht deniojda hcihw
.ytiralupop erom neve deniag I dna ,teb sih now soneX .senahpotsirA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.das dna detacilpmoc yrev s’tI
.rehtom ym neht dna rehtaf ym dellik dah
.mih dednimer rednaneM
.daer ot woh wenk ehs kniht ton od I .ymonortsa ro
si susageP‘ .stnemugra eht draehrevo I dna
.emas eht tsuj kool nrets a meht evag tub ,scitna rieht ta flesmih ot dehgual rednaneM
.noissessop sih ni skoob eht rednerrus tsum rellevart ro rotisiv yna taht wal a ti edam dah
,ylkciuq demrof dworc A
htiw meht derewsna tsuj ,soneX ,dneirf ym tuB“
.liat reh htiw gnilnaew eht gnittaws ,derekcihw ksuD
.daed gnol si skram eht fo rekam ro
,yrgnuh dna derit saw I“ ,deunitnoc eh ”,yawynA“
,detsurt eb dluoc I taht devorp I nehW
.snossel suoiverp nettogrof t’ndah eh taht gniwohs ,yltpmorp derewsna beZ
,stseirp dna sebircs ehT
”?skoob daer ot su hcaet uoy lliW“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.niaga mih dettaws-liat ksuD dna ecaf namhelf a edam beZ
.devirra dah flesmih susageP taht tuo gniyrc
,dluoc I sa yletilop sa rewsna ot deirt I tuB .modsiw sa mret
.yad taht nageb snossel gnidaer ym dna degnarra saw regaw eht tub
,hguone ylidaer deerga yehT
,nohponeX ,remoH
deciton I dna ,tsafkaerb nwo rieht ta erew sebircs eht elihw muirotpircs eht dnuora gnirednaw saw I
’.rednaneM fo ypoc ylno ruo netae sah
.ti raeb ot tsrif eht t'nsaw I tuB .keerG dlo eht ni 'ydobon' snaem rednaneM eman ehT“
.yrarbiL nairdnaxelA eht
nwo sih morf hguone tnereffid saw noisiv ym taht tuo derugif yllanif soneX tub
.tnecs rieht egnahc ot sevlesmeht no sgniht bur yeht ,etoyoC ekiL
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.eno fo tuo snoitseuq owt ekam ot deganam syawla tloc ehT
.edisni wolloh era taht enots fo selip taerg gnikam
ro gniyrrac rof sreniatnoc depahs tnereffid otni ssarg gnivaew ekil sgniht suordnow od meht tel taht sevooh dedivid revelc evah sgelerof riehT
,ecalp ’sirisO deprusu
,denialpxe rednaneM ”,serutaerc gnikool-railucep rehtar era yehT“
,skoob erom yna tae ot ton
.emit rehtona rof reh ot deneppah tahw fo yrots eht evael s’tel tub ,aihtnyK saw eman reH“
.dne eht morf gnuh taht gat yxaw eht rof tpecxe
.muepareS eht ta devil eh elihw denrael dah eh taht yrotsih ylimaf nwo sih fo stib ,esle gnihtemos dleh osla yehT .surypap fo sllorcs dna ,srettel keerG gnicnad
s’ti won dnA“ .reh dlot rednaneM
htiw dellif erew smaerd sih
.deciton evah neve t’ndluow I kniht I ,em netae dna gnola emoc dah drapoel a fI
,thgin taht otni lleW .won peels ot oG
,yltrela mih gnihctaw erew ecneidua siH
,drol elbaronoH‘ mih gnillet
”,yrots gnol a s'tahT“
.delkcuhc rednaneM .deksa beZ
’.uoy htiw yrautcnas rof ksa ot yppah eb lliw I ,ereh em rof ecalp a evah uoy fI
,naem yeht tahw dnatsrednu dna
yrarbil eht ni deniater saw lanigiro eht elihw
skram esoht ta kool nac lliks eht sah ohw namuh rehto ynA
”.tsol eb reven nac daed eht fo sdrow eht taht os ,skoob esoht rof egarots efas edivorp ot tliub era seirarbil dna ;skoob
”?naem rednaneM seod tahw tuB“
,eno elbon O ,ton su evaeL‘ dias dna em drawot deppets
,nettogrof ylraen dah eh taht tsap eht ni sgniht tuoba gnikniht
.reh ediseb deddon beZ
.sipareS dog eht fo muesum dna elpmet eht
,slaof owt nehw edahs eht ni gnizod doots ,flesmih susageP fo tnadnecsed ,esroh degniw tneicna ehT
”emaN siH toG rednaneM woH“ saw sihT
.dedda eh ”,yrros m’I“
,erar erew krow sih fo seipoC
,ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”,su llet mih tel dna ,beZ ,teiuq eB“
.owt uoy s'ti“ ,nageb eh ”,hA“
”.hsiw uoy fi emit rehtona erom uoy llet lliw I .emit deb
,muepareS eht fo tnediser a emaceb I taht saw ti os dnA“
,dekramer ksuD sa gninway saw beZ
rekaeps lanigiro eht fi neve
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.htron eht morf aes eht revo gnimoc yaw ym tsol I
?rehtom ruoy esol uoy did woH“
esimorp I taht noitidnoc eht no em evagrof yeht tub
.wodaem niatnuom ruo ni skoob on dah ew ylniatreC
yb emaN siH toG rednaneM woH:yojne esaelP
.enola etiuq ma dna rehtom ym tsol evah I
,stbuod emos meht nevig evah yam
’.eh eb tonnac dna stops kcalb
.edecca ot dalg oot ylno saw I hcihw ot dnamed a
.tcepxe ot tahw wonk t’ndid dna
dah ohw dog tnereffid a ro sirisO rof mrof wen a tsuj saw eh rehtehw raelc etiuq reven saw I
.eciohc nwo ym fo skoob gnidaer nageb I yllautnevE“
dellems ksed s’ebircs feihc eht no skoob llorcs eht taht
.elihw a retfa meht ot desu teg uoy hguohT“
.erofeb doog os gnihtyna detsat reven d’I
”,daer ot uoy rof skoob on evah I“
,wenk ehs sa sdnegel dlo eht fo hcum sa dna
.rehto hcae ot retteb llems meht ekam ot ro yerp rieht esufnoc ot saw ti rehtehw erus reven saw I
.sbreh dna sessarg teews dellems I dna ,mrotsniar suodnemert a morf delggardeb dna tew
”emaN siH toG rednaneM woH“
yrtemoeg fo em llet dluoc ehs gnihton saw ereht
...oot sgif erew erehT
,epacse ot deraperp dna
ssarg eht ni nwod dial I nehT“
”?uoy evah ,namuh a nees reve evah uoy fo rehtieN
.rewop taerg fo noitisop a ni saw eh tub
spihs rof robrah a dah dna
.flesmih ot delkcuhc esroh dlo ehT
’?daer dluoc taht esroh gniklat a fo draeh reveohW‘ gniyas
teef ym ot tog I
”,taht ot gnitteg tsuj m’I“
”.ereht srehto dnif thgim I gnikniht dnif dluoc I ecalp dethgil tseraen eht ot tnew I dna ,krad gniworg saw tI
.ti od ot hguone gnol saw liat reh taht won nrael ot nugeb tsuj dah ehs kcirt wen a saw tI
.eciov dehctip hgih sih ni detaeper beZ
neht snamuh htiw ecneirepxe tcerid on dah I esuaceb
.eunitnoc ot mih rof gnitiaw
.ylipeels ,deksa beZ
,rettiwT no ovitlA@( orevO ovitlA yb
”?neht ,degnahc teg eman ruoy did woh tuB“
.namuh a rof deman saw I
”.tnuoc ylbissop dluoc enoyna naht skoob erom deniatnoc dna ,suomaf yrev
,flesym pleh t’ndluoc I
.revewoh ,sgniht eseht fo enon did yehT“
?kcab ym no ediR
.llew sa em retfa ylerus saw eh
”?rehtafdnarg ,’skoob‘ era tahW“
.mih erofeb doots dna dehcaorppa ,beZ dna ksuD
.tniop siht ta detpurretni beZ
”,era uoY“ .deksa eh
’,rednaneM uoy llac tsum ew
.no tnew eh erofeb dezeens dna daeh sih derewol rednaneM
,surypap fo edam erew sllorcs esohT
.skoob fo seipoc edam sebircs eht erehw ecalp eht saw tahT
.derewsna rednaneM ”,od ew sa toN“
’.denibmoc tpygE fo seirarbil eht lla ni si ereht naht won uoy ni rednaneM fo erom evah uoy roF‘ .em dlot eh
,aes eht fo tsaoc eht no saw tI
.ti pleh t’ndluoc eh ,dehgual rednaneM
.muirotpircs eht fo nur eerf nevig saw dna ,tep
siht kniht I ’?keerG tnellecxe kaeps dluoc taht esroh a fo draeh reveohW‘
,mih ot denruter dna
,knird ot loop eht ot meht del eH
’.su hcaet dna yats tub
hceeps riaf em thguat aihtnyK rehtom ym hguoht ,roF
edam erew seipoc riaF
.reh tsol I nehw gnilraey a tsuj saw I“
.peels ot tnew dna
sralohcs dna stseirp siH
:srohtua suomaf rieht morf duola gnidaer saw I noos dna ,dekrow tahT
”.gninrom txen eht ereht em dnuof snamuh eht litnu yldnuos tpels I
,yletaidemmi eelf ot deen dluohs I esac ni
.dniw dna niar eht morf eseht ni retlehs ekat yehT
orevO ovitlA
.ti fo emos eta I dna
,em eveileb ,laer yrev saw ohw
.rehtom ym tsol I retfa thgir deneppah tI
.reh dlot eh ”,dlo snoom fo sruof ruof ylno saw I“
,dednal dah I erehw ,airdnaxelA fo trop ehT
,orevO ovitlA yb
.snamuh erom neve dna
,pot eht ta snroh s’llub a fo noitatneserper
.fooh ym htiw nep deer a dloh tonnac I
ecnis ,etirw ot denrael reven I dnA“ .dias rednaneM
.ylluftcepser daeh reh dewob ksuD
?gninnur morf em peek ot rehtegot sevooh ym niahc neve spahreP
.snoitan gniniojda ynam fo tub
.daer ot emit a ta eye eno ylno esu dluohs I taht
.tsol yleritne tsomla era syalp suomaf s’rednaneM
,ereht meht fo ynam erew ereht ,sesroh eht raeh dna llems dluoc I
saw tI .muepareS eht ta
.thgir saw ebircs eht dnA
,yrtnuoc taht fo gnik saw ohw ,ymelotP
.oot ynnuf llems yehT“
,skoob eht tae regnol on dluow dna
,sgel dnih rieht no klaw yehT
,tnemhserfer rof gnisuaP
eH‘ .noitcaer s’ebircs feihc eht saw
.airdnaxelA ta syad yppah sih gnirebmemer dna
”?ti t’nsaw ,gnirettalF
.rehtie ,uoy rof koob a ekam t’nac I oS
?pu em eit ot yrt yeht dluoW
”?gnihtemos tnaw uoy diD
,ecnetsixe ym tuoba wenk eh fI
.emulov tsal eht no gniwehc saw dna kcats eht fo tsom ffo dehsinif dah I laem rieht morf denruter sebircs eht emit eht yB
a etiuq emaceb I“
,sgnikram eht gnidnatsrednu elbuort dah I tsrif tA
.llew yltcefrep em devres rehtom ym morf denrael dah I keerG cittA eht dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
...suoiciled era yeht tub ,sgif wonk t’nod uoy ,lleW
,eceerG fo yrotsih eht ylno ton denrael I
.daer ot em hcaet dluoc eh taht swollef sih htiw teb a edam
”.lla meht detnuoc dah eno on taht
’!sipareS yloH‘“
”.htob si ti spahreP
”,noitnevni namuh a era skooB“
’.gnitirw‘ dellac skram elttil htiw yas yeht sgniht eht tneserper ot denrael evah snamuH“ .dias eh
,tpygE ni saw I tuB“
elohw eno eta dna
,etihw dna kcalb ni ees ylno uoy fi sroloc ynam fo esroh a si ohw
”'.redael' ro 'gnorts' snaem hcihw ,sotarK em deman rehtom yM
”?skoob eht eta uoy esuaceB
.htrof yad taht morf rednaneM saw I tub
”?rehtom ruoy ot deneppah tahw dnA“
.rednaneM deman retirw keerG suomaf a fo syalp eht deniatnoc skoob ehT
”?eman reh saw tahW
sah eno siht ,etihw yrevlis
.enots fo tliub ,snamuh fo ytic a ta devirra I ,oS“
.pu thgir seceipretsam sih netae evah tsum I
”?rehcaet a ydaerla uoy ereW“
.dah I ,yltnerappa ,os dnA
,onimA yrruF ,lysaeW
.gnitirw rof ecafrus talf htooms a ekam ot nwod dednuop si taht ssarg revir a
,srehto eht htiw ezod ot nageb eh tsal ta nehW
.lla ta dab t’nsaw ti dna
,skoob eht daer I esuaceb egdelwonk ni werg I .sgnitirw s’rednaneM eta reve ylno I“
.noitseuq txen s’ksuD saw
”?yrots eht gnillet si ohW“
.tey tsuj tpygE fo egaugnal eht nrael ot evah t’ndid I ,yletanutroF“
.neht yb dlrowrednu naitpygE eht fo egrahc ni saw sipareS dna
.sdaeh rieht koohs sretsgnuoy owt ehT
.evah dluohs I naht meht fo erom eta I dna
.hguoht ,rednaneM dellac syawla t'nsaw I“ .derewsna eh
,em devas tahw eb yam tI
htrofecneH‘ .daeh sih koohs ebircs feihc ehT
.gnizod ydaerla erew sgnilraey eht erehw
.gninrom eht ni yah yna em teg ot togrof enoemos nehw yad a emac erehT“ .dias rednaneM
,doog yrev saw ssarg ehT
.ytic namuh eht fo egde eht no nedrag a ni pu dedne dna tnecs eht dewollof I
.ekawa em peek dluoc gnihton ,derit os saw I
,sueZ dog tneicna eht esuaceb
”,eno elttil ,emit a ta gniht enO“
.egnarts tub ,tnasaelpnu syawla toN
,evorg enip elttil eht ot nwod neht dna
,dessarrabme ylbirret saw I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.tib a derekcins ksuD
si yrots s’yadot dna
a htiw ffats nezarb a deirrac ohw ,sipareS fo tseirp hgih ehT
skoob ynam os deniatnoc dna ,eguh saw tI
”.snaem ti tahw dna ,rehtafdnarg ,eman ruoy tog uoy woh gnirednow erew eW“
em detpecca ylkciuq ,rennam dezilivic a hcus ni kaeps dluoc I taht dehsinotsa tsrif ta erew yeht hguoht
?rehtafdnarg ,gnihtyreve wonk uoy yhw s’taht oS“
”?daed rieht rof kaeps ot snamahs evah snamuh t’noD“
’.gnilevart morf sniats dum sah tsuj eh spahreP‘ dnA
.sretsgnuoy owt eht no gnisucof erofeb ylsuoicipsus tuoba dekool dna elzzum sih morf tsud detrons ohw ,redle eht denekawa sevooh rieht fo elffuhs ehT
,muepareS eht fo nedrag nehctik eht ni peelsa nellaf dah I ,deneppah ti sA“
”.meht ot tnatropmi yrev era skoob oS“
,srats eht rednu ekawa doots susagep dlo eht
.daeh sih koohs rednaneM .ksa ot dah ehs
.yrarbil eritne eht ot ssecca eerf deviecer I
.ti dewehc dna ssarg fo lufhtuom llams a koot rednaneM