.trihs diputs sihT .etaH .gnikcuF .I
,kcen ym gnola esolc pu edir syawla sgniht esohT ?strap …palf
.siht hguorht seog enoyrevE
don llams a sevig eH .sllaf noisserpxe s’neR elcnU
,wodniw ssalg a dna eman eht tsuj ,lla ta sngis noen on
.trihs olop eulb thgil dna snaej ym ni tsuj
.aedi on evah I ?rehtruF ?resolC
,resolc nettog ev’I
,moor sih dna enim gnitarapes yawllah worran eht gnitaitogen m’I hguone noos dna
?gnihtemos gnidloh …s’eH
.niarb ym otni delip tihs erom deen t’ndid I fi sA
em ta slworg  dna
.nur dna nur I sa ydob ym hguorht kcor lwoh rehtona raeh I .ylevixelfer
?efas eb ot gniog tfil
eseht ,yduag os saw ti ,sterceS s’ollopA
…emos ,eninac evitunimid eht ees I nehw ruf ym fo tuo pmuj tsomla I ”!-hA“
,eno rehto eht ot teg ot deen I ,kcuf–kcolb rehtona dnuor ,evom I
,ereh nwod tekram eht fo klub eht pu ekat sbulcthgin elttil
.ytiniffAruF reh no
,dirg 62x62 a ni tuo dial si sevlehS eht fo roolf hcaE
,knim elttil a gnidloh s’eH
.retsaf dna retsaf ,retsaf ,erom gnivom ,gniod m’I tahw wonk I erofeb gnivom m’I
tub–thguoht I naht retal eb tsum
.ydob gnispalloc yldipar sih fo tuo llup ot seganam eH ”!og-
tuoba gniggarb elpoep
,suoivbo s’ti dna ,yas ot erom gnihtemos sah neR elcnU .tibah suovren a
eye ym litnu ,spohs elttil eseht fo kramedart a fo gnihtemos
-nrecnoc fo ngis tsrif eht ta tub ,daeh sih otni deneppah tahw maeb yllacihcysp dluoc I taht gnipoh ,mih ta kool I
llits ,saw I dehsur woh fo erawa yrev em edam ylneddus enola ti tuoba gnikniht ,eltsirb I
?etal taht yllaer ti sI
,54 hguorht 2 sleveL
,ydaets saw eciov s’dad yM
.eniF .yltpurba pu flesym llup I sa naorg dna kaerc yrgna na sevig deb ehT
.flesmih em tcatnoc ot ycneced eht dah neve t’ndah eh taht retfa dnA  –  ”.esimorp I
,noitanrebih rieht dna sraeb tuoba kramer sseletsat ytterp a tfarc ot egru eht tsiser t’nac I
,rehtraf gniog morf flesmih spots eh “-ehs ,newG“   ”.wonk I“
,srekrow fo lluf eb ot desu sevlehS reppU ehT
,yad eht gnirud em stxet eh netfo woh gniredisnoc ,krow hguone sseldnim ylgnimees s’tI
…ekil dna ,erugif I ,klim ddA
,ti ni rof gnikool m’I tahw wonk t’nod …I
,ecaf ym pu rehto eht gnibbur
.eno on s’ereht tub ,ecno saw reirret eht renroc eht ta kcab kool I ,rewol ti  leef I
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.tsaeb siht fo traeh eht gnola pu gnilacs
,ohce suonrevac ,gnilwoh
,drah sehcrul ehs sa ffo tuc teg I
.siht hguorht teg ot evah I
,eb ot dedeen ti naht redloc yletinifed saw tI
.enot ffurg eht stesffo nirg desuma yldlim reH
,god.ecioveht ta
.newG morf rettel a si teg I lla dna yb og sraey owt dna ,efil wen sih
.em dlot s’enoyna sa raf sa
,ystna os m’I yhw kcilc ot tnemom a sekat tI
.nwod mlac nac I erofeb tfil eht ta m’I
?siht llac d’eh revetahw
slrans eH ”!OG“  ”-truh er’uoY“
,kcolB tsaE eht ti llac ot desu rehtafdnarg ym rebmemer I
-enohp ym kcuf ,kcuf ”-llaC
…hu ta ekahsklim etalocohc tnim a gnitteg dna 42 m’I ?ton yhw dnA ?thgir ,ylraluger …tsuJ .on
,wap sih niats doolb eht gnihctaw ,dednuofbmud m’I
”.ti gnisol“ fo esneterp eht rednu yawa deterces dah I efink kaets a htiw moorhtab eht otni peerc d’I
,citceh oot ,ysub oot neeb s’tI
sdnarts neklis fo noisserpmi eht evig segde eht gnola depard ylsselerac ro ,saera ffo gnikcolb ,gnicnef utpmorpmi
,ylsuoixonbo skaerc syawla rood ehT
.won sraey wef a rof tuo ti gniworg neeb dah I
.enoyreve ni no gniog s’tihs ydaeh sihT
”.nisaB eht ssim I“
.nrettap fael dlog tahT
,ereht pu su rednu dnuorg ruo teg ot deen tsuj eW
,drawrof sehcrul eh sa tsirw tfel sih no derettalps dlog fo tnih elttil a dnoces a rof ylno ees I
.did eh fi erac ton dluow ylekil osla dna
?ereht ni od neve ti seod tahw
.skcots ecalp siht sgab etihw eht fo eno otni yldrazahpah gnihtyreve depmud ehs ,gab nwo ym thguorb I nialpxe ot moor em gnivig neve tuohtiw dna
.tesnus eht otni gnikool
?drawkwa  …fo dnik gnihtemos ,dnuos a dna
.driew …si ecnelis sihT
?reddal eht ekat I dluohs–reddal eht ekat dluoc I
.sbreh eht retaw dna rennid evah dna nwod tis ot evah I
,tsrif yrev ym ,nworg dah I tes ykcolb ,kciht eht sa rorrim eht ni ylknalb gniratS
.tae ot ydaer slwob owt
,esle erehwyreve naht retal hcum su ot semoc
,gnihtemos morf ro ot yaw rieht no ,tuoba gnillim era sklof emos yllausU
?yas nac I lla siht sI ”…uoy-y …uoY“
htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
.gniees m’I tahw rehtegot gniceip ylwols dnim ym ,ffo liart I
.esruoc fo ,tekraM 43 roolF on saw sihT
,yks eht gnola dehctolps gnitniap lio gnissapmocne dlrow ,tnaig A
.niaga peelsa s’ehs tub
pu gnikat sevlehS reppU eht ,flah ni dedivid
.roolf emas eht no ffo gnitteg saw reirret taht ..eH
,revlis ni eert eht derevoc
.gnol os koot-t ti yrroS“
.tnurg ro ,don ro ,ecnalg oN
.niaga htrae eht fo evig thgils eht leef ot
…gib eht denottubnu ylluf neve ,siht ekil kcen ym dnuora si ralloc eht thgit woh htiw laed ot od nac I gnihton s’erehT
,stcaer ydob ym ,swap yvaeh
,kcolB eht niatniam ot derih meht fo klub a ,ereh elpoep ecrof semocni llams dna seilimaf gnilggurts ynam
,ruf reh ni kram a ekil ,sevael dloG
.tekcop naej sih ni rehto eht ,tekcaj nat sih edisni dnah eno sah eH
,em htiw tnerap laer a eb dna yrt ot erised elbareuqnocnu ylgnimees s’neR elcnU dna eye gniyrp a gniraef
.nisaB eht ni loohcs ta saw I nehw
.NGISLLAC
,)?(oottat reh gniees em was yletinifed
I–flesym ti dootsrednu reven I
.seno eulb eht steg eh erehw tuo dnuof reven ev’I
,reeb sih mih ssap I
,rettib oot dnuos ton ot hguone wonk I
.yks ehT .ti ees I neht
.kcolB siht ekam ot lla
.ti ta gnikool niarts ylerab seye ym taht hguone wol tes nus eht
”?rennid rof emit s’ti nehw wonk em teL
.selbuab paehc dna sthgil yttops eht htaenrednu saw ti laicifitra ylraelc
”.emos teg annog saw I
,em tuohtiw gnivom si dlrow eht ekil sleef tI
,ereh morf neve ,ees nac I .reh
-dna ereht elif a evah I ,moorhtab eht ot teg
,yellaV eht otni nwod ti gnicart ,regnol tnemom a rof yks eht gnihctaw ,dnah ni ekahs ym hctulc I
.em ta skool eH .yssem
,reknip eht fo eno sehctac
,dnuora gnitarebrever
”.liat-etihW ,regnol gnitteg s’yad eht ykcuL
noitinumma mih gnivig syawla ,sedapacse thgin etal ym gnitautcnup syawla
”?taht rof senohp evah sdik uoy t’noD...“  -ro
.peed siht ton ,siht ekil sevlehS eht otni raf slevart
.srebma hcir otni woleb trid dna dnas eht gnitarutas
…ylevixelfer tsirw tfel reh gnippirg wap reh
.edistuo sbulc thgin yduag esoht fo eno otni dekrow ylikeehc gnihtemos yllausu
,erots yrecorg laer a
.kcolB eht no ecnanetniam ni gnikrow ,nam mlac a saw neR elcnU
,rellams a erehw ,83 no tfil eht fo ffo gnihsur
dniw fo tsug a fo yromem eht
.ni devom I ecnis sraey owt tsap eht revo fo duorp yletanitsbo os nworg s’eh ”nedrag“ eht htiw pu gnipeek m’I taht gnipoh
,dad ym htiw kcab ,eb ot desu tI
.won thgir ees ot deen t’nod I .ti tsap ezeerb I tub ,elbat eht no zzub llams a sevig enohp yM ?gnol woh
.hcuoc ynit ruo no kcab  snael dna
,pu naelc ot gniyrt tpek eh sa ecaf ym no noisserpxe dexifsnart eht tuoba deirrow ,siht hguorht em teg ot detnaw eH
.04 stih ti litnu esion sa daeh ym ni ssecorp ylerab  gnivom tfil eht fo scinahcem etuor ehT .srae ym fo tuo dnuos dekcus dah lwoh tahT .gnihtemos leef
,retteb ecaf ym emarf dluow ti gnipoh
.yawa dellup saw ti ekil
,erutcurtsarfni s’latipaC eht fo trap tnatropmi nA
,robal ,noitcurtsnoc ,sreenigne
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
…seod enihcam eht sa emit nrub ot deen I
.ni uoy evom ot deticxe er’ew
.der deniats saw ruf yarg kraD
,ylteiuq rood eht nepo dna yrt I .eniF
…ton s’tI“  “-ynohp a I mA
tuo gnihsur daetsni
,eseehc dedderhs fo kcap a dnif I
,yldam ,gninnur dna ekahs eht gnippord
.yas ot gniht gnorw eht s’tI
,noitcif trohs gnitirw won si dna tsiyasse na sa skrow ohw ,anueL yb
,lufituaeb neeb s’ti
”?haey ,ecin gnihtemos su teg
,nrettap taht nees ev’I ,etaciled
,em ta gnikool llits s’ydal raeb eht fi ees ot tsuj
,elttil a ruf daeh ym gnibbur
,reduol tuo trulb I ”!?ssiM“
,gniht nmad a yas t’ndluohs I wonk …I
.sknird yllausu erom …steews yllausu
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?emit eht evah uoy oD“  …hu
.enihcam eht morf ekahsklim eht gnillup
.ereht pohs ot nwod emoc
,lwoh fo dnik cificeps yrev A .lwoh a neht dnA
.moor ym ot og annog m’I .enif s’tI“
,yldrawkwa elffuhs I
.esuoh  ym ot ylsseldrow  em gnitolip
…tsuj ,enihw dekohc a tuo gnittel
ro …ro dnif ot  gniyrt m’I ekil ,seye ym dnuora dneb renni eht gnola gnicart
?gnihtemos ro sevlehS eht ni deyaled s’taht neve gnihtemos gnihtemos
.kcab yaw eht no ti knird I fi ,flesym rof gnihtemos ni kaens ylno ylbaborp dluoc I hguoht ,hguonE
,re–laem a ekil pu em gnizis s’ohw ,ksed eht ta ydal raeb eht strela esion gnirrihw ehT
”!yawa …kcuf eht-t …teG“
…dna eson ym ni kcuts ti
,thgit ylbatrofmocnu s’tI
.tol a deelb syawla sdnuow daeh esuaceb
”.uoy rof kcab emoc ot elba eb ll’ew dna
ot evah ton dna ni sdop ym tup dluoc I ,enohp ym derebmemer I fI .tfil eht ot ti ekam I sa leef ot gnilttesnU
,sdnah ym ni yllacitehtap yal
.mroftalp siht fo retnec eht raen gnimool gnidloffacs roiretni eht gninnacs
.moor laer a ,nedrag laer a ,ria hserf evah ll’uoy dna regnol elttil a tsuJ
,gnipraw si puc citsalp eht hguone thgit knird bmud ym gnihctulc m’I
,skcap odacova esoht fo eno s’ereht fi gniees ,noitces edam-erp eht dnuora gnikeep
krowdnuorg taht fo sehctap ynam htiw
.ti etaitnereffid ot spleh ti ta gnirats tub ,sevlehS eht ni tuo denword ylraen ti fo egnit cillatem ylthgil eht ,ti llems dluoc I .doolB
?noitacol lacisyhp on dah ti taht saw tniop eht thguoht syawla I naem
…saw …ti sselnu …sroolf owt ylno s’tI
.mih ot tseretni on fo saw I ekil
.kcolB eht fo ecaf eht revo gnihsaw
elihc revotfel fo llems eltneg eht ezilaer I erofeb tnemom a sekat tI
,dnah eno htiw gab eht hctulc I .em tsuJ
ti–pu desolc ydaerla dnats ecudorp eht
.hguone tsuJ .neR elcnU rof kcab eht morf nooM eulB a barg dna yenom ym kcehc elbuod I
”.siht hguorht seog enoyreve ,yrneH ,ehtaerB“  —  …dna
,ti no regnil ot ton yrt I
.mra delddir-ssalg reh fo daetsni ,tsirw reh ta gnikool ,delbmurg ehS ”…uoY !hW !?hN“  .tcatnoc ekam I erofeb tnemom a nepo pans seye reh tub
…B neht ,teertS C tsap ,tfil eht tsap ,teertS ht7 nwod gninnur ,tuo liab I
,newG morf rettel sselluos taht fo thgiew eht leef I
woh edih ot gniyrt erew yeht ekil
,sreltna eht morf yawa ward ro
,potpal a dleh ylno hcihw
.xoB s’arodnaP fo sutats lacigolohtym eht no ni hsac ot yletarepsed gniyrt ynam os ees ot driew si ti …tI
…ta stpmetta s’elcnu ym ot gninetsil fo sraey
,ydaerla ereh remraw tlef tI
,egdel eht ot esolc siht ecnerrucco nommoc erom a
,oot tsartnoc a
,noziroh dekaos yllacimehc eht gnola deraems thgil der kciht ,hciR
.der peed ylgnikcohs tsomla eht gnithgilhgih ruf hsi-yarg ,elap ym
,anueL yb ”sevlehS eht no retnuH“ saw sihT
,simetrA fo gnikaerB ehT
.roolf dnuorg ,05 ot 64 morf stuG eht dna
,ereht si neR elcnU
,snaej ym otni sdnah ym hsup ot gniyrt
.yrdnual ym od ot rednimer tnatropmi na sa sevres
a dnuora depraw yliratnemom teg
.htrae eht kramkcop taht syellav suonrevac eht ssorca morf elpoep tcennoc ot elba gnieb si ,yas yeht sa
.ti leef ot evah ton ot ydob ym ffo redluohs nwo ym deppir ev’dluow I
neht dna ,etalocohc tnim rof gnitpo ,enihcam eht otni sekahsklim esoht fo eno teg
…rof kool ot gnidneterp
,em tog rehtaf ym tfig gnitrap lanif eht
.rewohs gnidnats a htiw moorhtab llams a gnidulcni
?flesym gnissarrabme I mA ?evila I ma yhW
.llits lrig a tsuj
.niaga devom eb ot sdeen reve ti esac ni
.noisnet errazib siht morf desaeler ,eerf m’I  ,spots gnirrihw eht ,ylikcuL
.dniheb enohp ym tfel ev’I ezilaer I nehw
.redisnoc ot tnaw ton od yleniuneg I thguoht fo enil a nwod em gnirul
,em nees yletinifed s’ehS
.ydnah evah ot doog saw ti tub ,esuohrewop gnimag a yldraH
.suovren saw eh ,no dna no
”…enif eb annog er’uoy ,siht hguorht seog enoyreve ,larutan yltcefrep si sihT“
.retto revir eno eht htiw ,emina eno taht tuoba kniht I
,ysub flesym peek I   .roolf yreve no P-
…   .nisaB eht ot yllausu ,tuo etummoc ot evah ew ,ereh loohcs a yllaer neve ton s’erehT
.sekorts deredisnoc ,luferac ni nwod ruf ym gnipiw erofeb retaw ni lewot repap sih gnibbad
.tib elttil a rof eb ylno lliw tI“
.elims a fo hctiwt llams a tsuj kcarc ecaf ym gniees rebmemer I
!ylraelc os won taht ees nac I
.elprup fo snobbir yvaeh otni thgin gnimocno eht fo eulb krad eht htiw gnilgnim llits rehtruf dna
.mih morf lla ta gnihtyna
,ereh sgnigdol neve erew ereht
”sevlehS eht no retnuH“   yojne esaelP
tlef siht ekil em no tup eh thgiew railimaf eht ,htmraw siH
–   .elpoep lla fo newG
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.7 tsap-flaH...“  ”…ti tfel I“   .rah raH
,segnaro otni ti gnitulid
.oot ereht ti rof epicer eht tog dna xoB s’arodnaP ta airgnas fo etsat tsrif sih dah eh
.gnideelb s’eh …eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.hsac rof kcab og ot evah ll’I fi ro ,em no gnihtemos evah I
,top gib eht ni pu gnitaeh s’eh elihc eht ta skool eH
,ereht dna ereh retaw fo selddup suoiracerp eht gnola gnicnad thgil eht
.yllaer gnihtyna ,gnihtemos ,dehsam ,decid
elttil a gnihsarht fo dnik s’ehs …ehS
”sevlehS eht no retnuH“
21 roolf sa raf sa elpoep taht ti evah sromur
.swobniar kcils ni moolb ylbativeni mohw fo lla
.drawrof srebmul dna
.lwoh gnimlehwrevo rehtona htiw tem s’ti tub
,egnahc rof ksa ot yrt neve t’nod I
–  …uoy sessim rehtaf ruoY
,seye ym morf ti gnipiw ylidaets dad ym htiw ecaf ym nwod gninnur doolb
.lufepoh ylgnisirprus s’ti stsisni eh ,dlrow eht fo dne eht tuoba s’tI .hguorht gniwehc neeb s’eh wohs a no stup eh litnu
rewsna na evah ot smees eno on tub
,elsia na otni ylkciuq yawa knils I
.larutannu gnihtemos
,sgnaf gnirab s’eH
,sgab citsalp fo gab gib eht ni sgab citsalp dlo eht fo eno barg I dna eciohc on evah I
,skcolb fo retsulc elddim eht ffo gnikcol
daeh I .htuos og sthgif lausu ruo dluohs
.ecno ta nwot tfel dna sesuoh rieht fo tuo nettog dah enoyreve ekil ,hcamots ym ni tip a tuo gnivrac ,gninword
,ereht tuo klaw ot doog sleef tI
.emit eht lla nosaer on rof pu sedir ti ,thgiewrevo ylbirret ton m’I elihw dna
.stoob yvaeh yb detautcnup spetsfooh gnikcalc ym ,gnivael m’I
.krow eciffo rof dezimitpo dna ,dlo sraey owt won
.enoemos teg dluohs I …I“
,esuoh eht morf skcolb owt tuoba ,9F fo renroc eht dnuor I nehw esrow steg ti dna
.htaerb rof gnipsag ,roolf eht nO
?ees I did tahW …ees I
.teertS ht7 hguorht sehsaw taht noen llud eht ni flesym ysub ot ytinutroppo eht gnikat daetsni
,liathgih ot ydaer ,gnisnet sgel ,stug ym otni flesti gniworrub cinap
,spets gnippolc
,ti morf gnitcarter ylneddus neht
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
…tnarraw t’nseod taht neve tub ,ygolopa na tuo delbmum fo dnik I
,ecnelis ni odacova dna eseehc ruo edivid ew
,eye ym fo edisni eht dnuora gnivom yltcefrep
…   .rehtegot ti eceip t’nac I tuB
,sevlehS eht tuoba gnihtyreve ekil ,tI .htrae eht otno speerc ylwols gnirps eht sa staoc kciht
.motnahp a ekil em ot gninruter tsud nwo ym fo gnileef eht
.dik ,naem I tahw wonk uoY“
,yzzirf lla ruf daeh
,txen reh morf pu semoc enihw A
,taerg gniod er’yeht esuaceb ereh pu sdne yllaer eno oN .sevlehS eht ni railimafnu ton gnileef a s’tI
.nehctik eht morf eciov s’neR
.esruoc fo ,nepo saw tikskiuQ eht
?eramthgin fo dnik emos gnivah ehs saw ,cinap dliw tahT
.ybraen tuo dial saw pirts tekram htap netaeb-eht-ffo erom
,won kcolB eht tsuj s’tI .era ereht srehto ynam woh neve ro
dniheb ssalg eht hguorht gnikcarc woble
,yttirg dna dimuH ?mraw ,ekil dnA
,hO“  .ereht morf gnimoc
”-ssim …hU“  .esac yalpsid
,elpmis era stnorferots ynam ,wolg reisor
”-enoyrevE“  anueL yb
,gniksa flesym dnif I
,elsia eht fo renroc eht dnuora keep I
.traeh latem digirf eht pu gnitaeh yllud
.roputs ym fo tuo em llup ot hguone saw tikskiuQ eht ni CA eht dna ,gnicar s’ti ekil sleef dnim ym emit siht yB
saw emit eht ta ffo gnikniht saw I lla …tub
.thgir eb ot gnipoh ,sseug I
.tlep reh otni gniddebme ssalg fo sdrahs
,siht ekil steg syawla tI
43 no tramwaP eht ot pu neve ro tikskiuQ eht ot spirt eseht no og yllausu I swonk eh fi rednow I dna
”.evah ot ecin eb ll’tI ?odacova na ebyaM“
,sevlehS eht gnola ecnalg ot tnemom a ekat I
pu gnikam sniahc esooL
.peehs a fo pils elttil eht ,sessalg dnuor yrev reh htiw gnola reh gnimarf
,leets yarg fo bew etacirtni eht gnola pu gnitarebrever enot latem yltcnitsid hcae ,gniohce sevooh ym fo dnuos eht raeh I
,yawa yletaidemmi neht dna ylfeirb em ta secnalg eH
”.kaerf fo dnik emos ton er’uoy ,diK“
tsomla s’ti tub ,ti no sucof
.sreltna ym dnuora egdod yltaen ot gniyrt
elbaresim esoht ssim I .nisaB ssim I
,taht otni tup saw troffe fo tol A
.peelsa ylraelc ,setteragic eht tpek yeht erehw llaw eht tsniaga kcab gninael ,tnorf eht ta ydal raeb gib eht ot eye-edis a tnarraw ot hguone
eht si–si tfil eht erehw t’nsi siht ,dnuora nrut
.eciov gnilbraw sih hguorht dekaos ,niap
,loohcs ni kcab erifdliw ekil daerps taht sromur errazib esoht fo eno s’tI
.hguone s’ti tub ,elbahsiugnitsidni roloc lanigiro s’trihs sih
,pu reh gnignirb ni ekatsim sih gnizilaer yletaidemmi tsomla
.siht hguorht seog enoyrevE
,kcils tekcaj kcalb sih
.neht redluohs ym no dnah sih dah dad yM
.egdirf depmarc ruo otni dedaol erawreppuT eht hguorht gnikcip ,aera nehctik ynit eht otni sevom ylpmis eh tub
mih llet ot traeh eht t’ndah I
.niaga gnihctiwt si rae yM
taht dniw laer on s’ereht ,evom ylerab sniahc eht ,hguoht ereH
,deciton t’nsah ylekil eh taht daeh ym fo kcab eht ni gniwonk ,yawa kool I
.eno eulb erar a kcip dna hguorht tros ot tnemom a gnikat neve
,anatak sih fo tlih eht ni enicidem ,ekil dah eH
.mih no stoob yvaeh ,kciht eciton tub pleh t’nac I
ti tub ,trihs siht ni nepahssim
.traeH s’etidorhpA rof ngis eht htiw edistuo tem m’I ,tnemom a rof dna ,yrruh a ni tfel I
.peed oot ni steg ti erofeb noos tuo taht kcip ot evah ot gniog s’ehs tub ,yawa thgir reh truh t’now ylbaborp tI
,nwod gab ym yal I moor ym otni gnilbmutS
,moor ym ni skcans robrah ot
.tfil eht fo  roolf eht gnola gnikcalc sevooh
.elihw elttil a tsuj
,hgU  –   ”.ti ees nac I ,tes lager yllaer a otni worg ot gniog er’uoY“
.gnihtemos gnidloh saw eh …I
,srehto eht ot deneppah sah tahw ot
G“   .thgirb yllufniap tsomla ,seye eulB .eulB
,nekorb …skool eH ?thgiR .flow A
.pu devom dad ym retfa ecurt ydaetsnu nA .gnipeekecaeP
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.oot taht od ot deen I ,thgiR
.tsuj I .siht retfa toN
.wodniw tnorferots dekaos-der eht fo renroc eht no ,ereht s’tI
,eseehc fo tuo er’eW .hu
.haey …I“  ”?yako uoY
ssalg eht tsniaga
…emitrevo gnikrow eb ll’I ,syad wef txen eht krow ta no gniog gniht gib a s’erehT
,retnec eht ta traeh eht dnuora gnitaitogen
.eerT samtsirhC dlo ruo revo epard ot desu dad ym woh ekil ,slessat ekil ti fo ffo gniregnil
?thgir ,05 a eb attog s’tahT
,hctiwt ot strats rae tfel yM ”.gnihton s’ti
.dik ,deirrow gnitteg saw I“  .der fo stoL
.eliforp ni nam enipul deifingid ,gnikool yletats a fo ecaf eht slaever ti ,pu delpmurc ,stnap ym ni eton a s’ereht ,ylluficreM
stsisni ohw regdab ykculp eht ,seniaR erodoehT ssim I ,sessalc
-ro ,ta kool ot enohp a ro ,cisuM
,efiw wen sih htiw adogaP ykS eht ot ffo nar dna sevlehS eht otni dik sih dedraob tsuJ
,04 no peed siht si ti yad fo emit tahw ecnalg a ta llet ot ysae reven s’tI
,yrehpirep eht ni newG ees dluoc I .detniat
,skram esaerg kcalb htiw deniats syarg llud esiwrehto eht gnola gnicnad thgil eht gniees
,sekahsklim esoht redisnoc ot dnim a flah evah I
”.thginot ecin yllaer s’tesnus ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
…yeH“   ”.emit s’ti ,ymereJ“
.seitnewt sih ni reed a ot gnitlusni sa ffo emoc ylno nac tub eb ot snraey ylraelc eh gnihtemos
,lwocs ot smees ehs sa ,hguoht ,detrevid elttil a steg thguoht fo niart yM
.revo lla ekahs neerg hsug dna flesti otni dneb ot gninetaerht
.htap tnereffid a gnikat ,ydaerla enog s’eh tub ,kcab ecnalg a gnicnahc ,rekciuq klaw I
,morf emac ti erehw ees ot nrut I .egde eht ffo gab eht dna knird ym pord tsomla I .niaP .tnemal a
.renroc eht ni yawa dekcut ,kniht I ,reirret fo dnik emos
.ti fo skool eht yb ,selif lian
”.wonk I ,haey ,siht hguorht seoG“
fi ees ot stekcop ym gnikcehc ,esruc I
.kaeps t’nac I tub ,thgir ti ekam ot gnihtemos ro ,tluaf sih ton s’ti …taht mih llet ot tnaw I
,gniohce eht ,thguoht fo enil siht tuB
,ekawa reh ekahs dna yrt ot tuo gnihcaer
,taht retfa yltpurba moor ym otni flesym llup fo dnik I “-
,traeH s’etidorhpA .sngis evitcudes erom
,tfol eht ni dah I stnalp lisab dna yramesor eht nopu thguorw I lleh tahw
,srenid regaem emos
.emoh og ot evah I
,hguoht rewsna na rof dnuora tiaw t’nod I
.nwo reh gniteem pu dedne seye ym ecno
,rellud a ,ti ni gniremmis tub ,thgil laicifitra ni dehtab ssel si 83 no teertS ht7
,eniw ekil gniwolf doolb ,tsehc sih  ni seloh owt gnitartsnomed
,ylevixelfer wollaws I
.esuoh s’etoyoc siht otni tel eb ot gniggeb retcarahc niam eht gniees gnihton leef I
.ytsud werg ria eht yaw eht etsat llits nac I
,oga gnol …saw tahT
…ekil eht dna erofeb thgin eht ti tisiv ot elba gnieb yllaer
,elzzum reh morf tuo selbbub yltneg lworg wol a
,suoicsnoc fles leef syawla I
.ffo teg …ot evah I
.seye ym gnillor em sehctac ehs erofeb yawa nrut dna don kciuq a evig I
J dna 71-01
.emarf eht htiw gnoldaeh dedilloc dah taht reltna eht fo bun eht gnibbur ylevixelfer dnah a ,nwod yal I sa kaerc yldognu na sevig deb ehT
?tahw wonk uoy ,hE“  .sgurhs neR
.moorhtab eht otni kaens ot egru gniwalc eht
…neeb s’tI .ti gnibbur peek I
.em eganeet dekcohs llehs yrev a ekil dekool evah tsum tahw eldnah ot deirt eh sa tneitap
.retnuoc eht otno seirecorg ym dna 05 eht tuo gniyal ylkciuq
-revaw llams a s’ereht ,kcuf ”-tsuj I .ma I
s’erehT .ffo gnirepat erofeb elttil a elzzum ym nwod
,gninrut daeh ym ni sraeg eht leef nac I
”-ot ffo uoy era erehW“
?elttil a ti tlem
maerts eno ,ecaf ym gnola nur dah doolb
.seman rieht ni snup elinevuj htiw seno ssarc eht t’nera yeht nehw
.gnihtemos deen I yhw si  sihT
.llits liam-e taht tuoba gnikniht neeb sah eh taht gnituo elihw
eht yaw eht ,dekool ti woh
,sehctiwt rae yM ?detuM
kcuF“   .hsarht a htiw emarf rood eht otni sreltna ym kconk yletaidemmi tsomla dna rood ym otni
dah enoemos ekil dekool syawla tI