.ereht eb ot tnaw I tuB   ...   .enog m'I
,regniR ratS sa nwonk osla ,xoF rolyaT yb
,tsohg a m'I ebyaM
,mih dnA   .uoy htiW
;si ytilibasiD fo eluR tsriF eht swonk enoyrevE
,eci rednu deppart neeb ev'I
.kcab teg ot woh enola tel
,og I regnol eht ebyaM
,relevart wollef ruoy floWcaM boR si sihT
,ydob ym dnif ot woh wonk t'nod I
.stnemom gnikaw ym semusnoc tnemelpmi tsum I hcihw tahT
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
.gnidnatsrednu dnA
,ytisoreneg taht yaper ot tnaw I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.meht fo lla dna ,reh dna
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,xoF rolyaT yb
.efilretfa citsitrA
.elpoeP daeD eeS yeht taht seno devol ym ot no tel reven ot tseb ym yrt I
noitaerc dna noitaedI
.redaeR ,terces ym s'tahT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.retaw gnizeerf ,dloc eht ni peed
,”ehtaerB I“yojne esaelP
.evah nac I dediced ydaerla evah thgim ,dneirf ym ,uoy taht gnihtyrevE
.elbaliava ecruos yreve morf gninnuc dna htgnerts gnikees
.semoceb eci eht regnorts dna rekciht eht ,gniliaf
.sgniht esoht tuohtiw niw ot htap a fo thguoht eno on dnA   .t'nac uoY .oN
,degnahc ylneddus reverof devol ev'uoy emag taht fi sA
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
,gniyrt peek I sselnu
,si ti sa derracs dna degamad
.reverof ,liaf ot demood
?stooB hsaD eht teg ot tnaw uoY   .t'nac uoY .oN
ytiniffAruF no dnif nac uoy ohw
.kciht oot si eci eht ,won ,ebyam tuB
”ehtaerB I“ saw sihT
?ssordnA tnorfnoc dna moneV fo shtped eht otni dnecsed ot tnaw uoY   .t'nac uoY .oN
.sregnif ym hguorht esahp etaerc ot sloot eht tuB
.ytilibasiD ruoy tuoba klaT t'noD
.niaga rednu deggard gnieb erofeb
.deriT syawlA m'I
.yticapac yna ni ,htaed rof deraperp ton m'I
."sisorelcs lanips-orberec elpitluM"
.enips dna niarb ym fo sevren eht ni demrof evah sreirrab lacisyhP
.tra ekam ot tnaw   yletarepsed   yltaerg I
,lliw reven I dnA   .ecarg dna ,evol
?ksaM notaeK eht yub ot tnaw uoY   .uoy rof tsuj
.htgnerts eht rof hcraes I
.sisorelcS elpitluM evah I   tub
,ehtaerb ot elba neeb dna eci eht hguorht kaerb ot deganam ev'I
.ekirts ot erehw tniopnip ot ssenrevelc ehT
.denword ydaerla ev'I ebyaM
.niaga ehtaerb ll'I ,noos ,ebyam dnA
.ecneitaP .emit deen I
xoF rolyaT yb meop a
.gnihtaerb sa ma I ohw ot laitnesse si
.gnivil eht htiw niagrab dna fo ksa I
.ti rof gnivirts pots reven lliw I
.daD regdaB yldduC eht ,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR   .ykseulB dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot