.em yfitnedi ot demees yeht ,yaw a nI
.yltsenrae tnatsissa erots eht detsisni
.hgual kaew a evag I ".togrof
"kniht I" "?pu s'tahW"
.od ot detnaw I tahw yltcaxe dezilaer I
.srekrow-oc ym fo klat eht eb ot redro ni syadirF nwod-sserd no eciffo eht ot raew dluoc I taht trihs sseletsat ,ynnuf ,ylgu ym
.delahni I "...I" .nwod dekool I
.noitcarf a neve ton
.no won morf enilno gnippohs ym gniod ebyam deredisnoc dna seitnap fo riap eht pu dekcip I yltnatiseH  .deniamer ti
.egapbew rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.dnim ni redneg htiw dengised t'nsaw tI
”raewrednU raeW reveN I“ saw sihT
,kcuf ,kcuF .thguoht I ,kcuF
"?ris ,sruoy ton yletinifeD .ees I" .dias eh "hO"
egnarts os demees tI
tnatsissa selas eht ,edutitarg fo noitcelloc delffum a htiW ".ylevol
,niatruc eht nepo ot tnaw t'ndid I emit sihT
,yawa devom eh sA ".tnemom
- trihs ykcat ym eb dluow tI
.noitailimuh htiw gninrub skeehc detaeh ydaerla ym ,dehsulf I
,detcepxenu os ,eciov ehT ".ris em esucxE"
"?thgirla gnihtyreve si" ,derettuts eh "sI"
.enif si gnihtyreve ,seY .seY"
"yrt ot detnaw uoy taht trihs eht evah I ,riS"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,tsehc eht dnuora snottub eht gnilluP
tnereffid htob ,sdaor owT
.sregnif ym neewteb revo neht gnidlof
.ecnatropmi hcum os evah ot demees gnihtolc fo eceip eno siht taht
,no kcab snaej ym dellup I erofeb tsuJ
.ylisae etiuq tif ti ,hguone eruS
.elbatrofmoc erom erew ylurt yeht fi derednow I
”raewrednU raeW reveN I“:yojne esaelP
.bew s'redips a sa eligarf sa gnihtemos fo edam erew ti fi sa
,gab ym otni esahcrup ym dils I sa deksa I "?seY"
.hcneb eht otno kcab meht deppord I ,swap ym ni stnemragrednu eht pu gnillaB
,retsgnuoy eht ot gniyl rof dab elttil a tlef I
eht evig ot dednetni erew sehctits tnedifnoc dna dlob eht ebyam
,tuokcehc eht ot edorts dna niatruc eht nepo kcab werht I
.ti gniyub no delttes dah dnim ym ydaerlA
.delbmum I "muideM"
dekool yletinifed yehT
.em ediseb pu deirrucs tnatsissa eninac gnuoy eht ,os did I sA
"?no yrt ot sehtolc yna gnirb ot togrof uoY"
".raewrednu raew reven I
.don yldneirf a mih evag dna noitcarf a niatruc eht nepo deggut ,dehgis I
.trihs lufwa siht esahcrup tsuj
,ydob ym detah I
"sey..Y" .retsaf gniworg
.gniht fo epyt siht rof koobyalp a yltcaxe ton s'erehT .wonk t'ndid I
ot thgir eht evah eh diD
.ytirecnis fo noisserpmi tseb sih gnivig spil eninac sih ,em ta delims eH
.drac tiderc ym rof tellaw ym ni dnuora gud I
htaerb ym gnihctac ,ereht detiaw I
.raewrednu ym fo lla ecalper ot deriuqer eb dluow ti fi derednow I
erow elcibuc eht yb doots ohw nam gnuoy ehT
.evah dluoc eh ytirohtua fo dnik tahw derednow I dna ,seitnewt ylrae sih otni ylerab eb ot dekool god ehT
- elam deraeppa ylniatrec kcab dekool taht em fo noitcelfer ehT
taht dediced I ,spih ym dnuora meht gnilffuhS
,ti ta dekool I taht won ,saw tI
.meht gniyub fo aedi eht ot demotsucca flesym teg ot
srexob erow syuG
?moor gnignahc eht ni sfeirb ruoy tfel evah yam uoY" ,nageb eh
.em dniheb elcibuc eht ro ,ydob ym fo erom yna laever ot ton suoituac gnieb ,ti dnuora daeh ym dils dna
.tuo lla meht worht dna emoh og tsuj ot gniog t'nsaw I ,on
,sfeirb eht pu gnipoocS
.em ot regnarts tnatsnoc a ekil gnileef ,ni dnuora deklaw I taht gniht neila egnarts siht
.neht etelpmoc eb dluow yregrus yM
,rehto hcae ot txen detaeS
.trihs a em hctef ot gniyrruh saw ohw krelc erots eht dna
.dehsinif saw noitisnart eht retfa neve
.gniraew saw noitces strops eht ot txen revo niuqennam eht taht eno ehT .pot
.mrofinu erots desserp ylenif a
- no sehtolc tuohtiw em ees ot mih tnaw t'ndid yllaer I .ton depoh I
.gniyl saw I taht erawa ylluf fi sa
.ytinilucsam lacisyhp ym fo foorp eht laecnoc ot tnaw t'ndid
.thguoht eht fo ecruos eht fo thgis eht htiw gnola hsinav dluow tnemegduj
.acimroF fo edam neeb evah llew sa yam yeht taht
,sregnif ym tsniaga niht oot elttil a
.namow a ro nam a saw I fi erac t'ndluow trihs ehT
.tey seitnap yna nwo t'ndid I
.esle ydobemos fo erutcip a ta gnikool fi sa ,kcoc ym ta gnirats ,ereht gnuh seye yM
.togrof I kniht I ,oN" .gnikcarc eciov ym ,dias I "oN"
?I t'ndluow ,sfeirb ym fo lla tuo worht ot evah dluow I ,neht tuB
,meht raew llits dluoc I dna ,sriap lareves dah I
"yrros m'I ,hO" .daeh ym koohs I
.trihs eht rof gnihcaer
.no ti deppils I ,ylevitatneT
.stnemragrednu desahcrup-
,desuap I ...nehw ton
,dias eh "ris ,em esucxE"
,erew yeht taht demussa dah I
,flesti yb lla ksir eguh a tlef dah meht htiw moor gnignahc eht otni gnitteg fo tca ehT
?elcibuc eht ni kool ot ksa
- regral deraeppa yletinifed sfeirb ehT
noen yllaicifitra os dekool taht stesnus dna selppaenip egnaro ,seert mlap eulb fo egalloc a saw tI
.esoohc ot tnaw t'ndid I tuB
".llats eht otni tnew I nehw ereht erew yehT
.ylkciuq oot ,deilper I "seY"
,seitnap eht ediseb nwod meht tes I
dluoc I taht os seitnap eht htiw edis-yb-edis tis meht tel
.sfeirb raew ,ylbatrofmoc etiuq ,llits dna namow a eb dluoc I
,reihsac eht ot revo meht gnidnaH
.meht rof gib oot erew ttub ym fi derednow I
.trihs eht htiw enola em gnivael ,yawa deklaw
si yrots s’yadot dna ,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.detnaw I revenehw meht raew ot elba eb dluow I
.erofeb gnihtolc eninimef nrow yllautca t'ndah I tub
”raewrednU raeW reveN I“
"?oot seitnap fo riap a spahrep ,mhu ,dnA
.thguoht I ,meht ot evig fo tol a evah did yehT
,cihc s08 ykcat fo hsalc
emit ’sraey a ni ,esruoc fO
.mih fo dir teg ot detnaw tsuj I
,hself fo eceip taht yb degduj - degduj tlef I
hcaeb eht no nwod meht tes I ylluferaC
,raef fo hsur a tlef I "...dna
"?eb ti t'ndluow yhW
tsuj tlef cirbaf ehT
niaga tuhs niatruc eht dellup I
.trihs eht dedlof I ,sredluohs ym morf ti gnippilS
,dereffo I "uoy knahT"
.rehto eht ro enO
.eciov sih ni ssensuovren fo elbmert thgils a ,dias eh
,thguoht I ,dluoc I
"ni emac uoy taht deciton ew ,tsuj s'tI"
,tuB .moor gnignahc eht oT"
.erots eht tfel dah I emit eht yb edaf dluow gnileef eht wenk I tub
niatruc s'elcibuc eht fo edis a pu dekculp I
,gninruT .pmuj em edam
.erus t'nsaw I tnemom a roF
.enim ton yletinifeD" .daeh ym koohs I
.rehto eht ro eno kcip ot deen t'ndid I
,ecalp otni kcab edils sfeirb ym tel I .kcuf
.taht rof ti devol em fo trap kniht I
- kniht ot tnemom a detnaw tsuj dah I
.saw I dekan woh fo erawa ylesnetni emaceb dna
,sfeirb ym evomer ot detrats dna
- pohs siht ni smoor gnignahc eht ekil t'nerew stnemragrednu ehT
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
.em ta kcab erats ot demees ,drawkwa dna rednels ,ydob yM
sserP straeH peeD yb
.sfeirb saw emoh ta ebordraw eht ni dah I gnihtyrevE
,elttil a delffuhs eH
.deilper eh "ris ,esruoc fO"
.sfeirb fo riap a tub gnihton gniraew
.selcibuc gniruobhgien eht ni nem eht fo seye eht yb
.kcis leef ot gnitrats saw I ,dog hO .derettuts I
,ni doots I elcibuc moor gnignahc s'nem eht dna
.enim ton er’yehT" ,dias I
.elgna yreve morf ti gninimaxe ,dnim ym ni dnuora aedi eht dellor I ,tnemom a rof gnisuaP
.taht wolla t'ndluow ylerus yeht ,eno elamef eht esu llew yrev t'ndluoc I
"?deen uoy od ezis tahW"
,oot rekciht erew yehT
.edistuo morf ecov eht emac "riS"
.noitatcepxe na saw tI
.esae ot gnimees noicipsus sih fo elttil a ,deddon eH ".gniraew
,ti delaecnoc taht sfeirb eht yb
,stnemragrednu eht fo lairetam eht ta deggut I ylthgiL
.hcneb eht no stnemragrednu eht ta kcab dekool I erofeb etunim lluf a tsomla em nekat evah tsum tI
.rorrim eht ta dekool dna elcibuc gnignahc eht fo kcab eht ta tas taht hcneb eht otni nwod depmuls I
fo rohtua dna ,seinapmoc elpitlum rof retirw GPR potelbat a si ohw ,ebyC nosilA yb
...dna ,llet ot yaw on dah I
.senob esool ekil elttar ot deunitnoc sevren ym sa
.srexob ro ,meht erow rehtie I
.gniworg dehsinif dah stsaerb ym ecno ti netsaf ot elba eb dluow I fi erutcip ot deirt I
.detnaw I revenehw meht raew dluoc I ,taht retfA
.fitom naiiawaH ylgu ylevisneffo tsomla na gniraeb ,swolley dna seulb krad fo hsem suoedih a
.meht yub dluohs I fi derednow dna ,swap ym ni dleh I taht seitnap fo riap llams ,niht eht ta derats I   ebyC nosilA yb
.niarb ym otni yaw sti nrub detaerc ti taht citats lausiv eht gnittel ,tnemom a rof desuap I
shgiht ym tsap nwod meht gnidils
nu no yrt t'ndluoc ylniatrec dna ,yllaer ton
.redluohs ym ot esolc gninael
...dna ,uoy htiw ni gnihtyna ekat uoy was ydobon ,llew
.lairetam elbarud erom a fo edam dna tsiaw eht ta rediw
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.shtap owt em gnireffo eb ot demees seitnap eht dna sfeirb eht
.taht ni tsenoh ylegnarts saw ti tub
.ytinilucsam deggur fo noisserpmi
.meht ta derats dna kcab denael
,taht dna yaw siht meht denrut I
fo esnes eht taht gnipoh
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.elims em edam ti ,nosaer emos roF
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ebyC nosilA yb
.gnilbmert sevren ym ,deksa I "?seY"
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
yeht fi sa ,pu yaw eht lla sfeirb ym llup ot gnilliw erew yeht erofeb deregnil sdnah yM
?moor gnignahc stneg eht fo tuo em redro eh dluoC
.seloh eht hguorht emit a ta eno waptoof hcae gnitfil dna
.ylsuoludercni elttil a ,deksa eh
.dnah ni trihs ylgu ykcat ym
- reidruts kool ot dengised erew yeht ebyaM .thguoht I
.tnemom a eb t'now I .esruoc fO" .deddon god ehT
.teef sih fo sdap eht no gnikcor
,ecalp ni kcab snaej ym gninetsaF
.guns elttil a spahreP .dediced I ,ecin
?nosirapmoc lausiv a ward
.feiler fo hgis a devaeh dna
.ylevol eb ll'ti erus m'I"
,em enifed ot deen t'ndid tI
.no meht dellup I
?gnikniht neeb I dah tahw ,thguoht I ,ti nmaD
,srae gnipoord gnol ,ecaf tibbar sih no elbbuts niht
,syawla ekiL .t'ndid tI
,sehtolc yna no yrt ot dednetni neve t'ndah I
.ylwols ,dias eh "ees I"
”eibmoz eganeet yag a saw I“
.evisulcxe yllautum dna
.seitnap eht ediseb dnuorg eht ot meht gnippord dna swaptoof ym ffo yltfiws meht gnippihw
,tsehc ym ni dnuop ot detrats traeh yM
.elttil a tsuj meht gnixelf
.yug a t'nsaw I tuB .sfeirb ro
a saw tI .elamef ro elam yltnerehni saw taht ti no gnihton saw erehT
,nwod kcab sfeirb ym deggut I
.rorrim eht ni ezag ym tem yliraropmet taht noitcelfer eht ta gnicnalg
eulb eht no yrt ot detnaw I .seY .seY"
decitonnu yawa meht laets ot gniyrt neeb dah I fi sa
"?ris ,neht pleh yna deen uoy diD"
,noitom kciuq a htiw ,nehT
dna ffo sfeirb ym pihW
degduj saw I sa hcum sa tsuj
,em ta derats god ehT