”.ereh emoC .nam ,gaf a eb t’noD“ saw dias htuom ruoy lla dna
.su no ti llems dluoc eikcaJ     .rewsna taht ni
su fo derdnuh a erew ereht ebyam ,tonk kciuq a saw I ebyaM .em rof erac ot emac reven uoy ebyaM
,koob kcalb elttil a ni seiceps yreve rof yrt ot
.elttil a knard I ebyaM
?srettel tsal esoht ni saw tahw wonk uoy oD     .etorw I llits tuB
,htlaew s’natlus a htiw uoy denigami I
uoy nehW .enoyna dlot eh fi ffo liat sih etib d’uoy regnessem eht dlot uoy dna ,ssa erab ruoy ni ti deviecer uoy ,ynamreG ot kcab og ot su rof emac redro eht nehW
,ereht neeb evah d’uoy fI
.uoy saw ti wenk I tub ,dehsilbup reve saw eman oN
.won ereh m’I yhw s’taht sseug I dnA
.occoroM morf devom stnerap ruoy retfa pu nworg d’uoy erehw dna
,sraey dna sraey retfa em esirprus ot detnaw uoy skniht naeJ
,taeh eht tuoba ylsseldne gnihctib dna ,seye ruo ni nus eht rebmemeR
yaw eht ,ti dleh thgil eht yaw eht
.og ot em sehsiw ti reverehw ,yawa raF
.ebolg eht fo renroc yreve morf sthgilf-eniw ekil nem gnitsat ,dlrow eht dnuora gnittestej uoy denigami I
,selttes ti tsal ta nehw
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,ijustihoK yb
.eviecer dna dnes ot noitisop a ni erew uoy nehw ,sliame dna stxet eht lla ,gnitiaw ym rebmemer t’ndluow uoY
.hteet ym uoy dewohs reve I emit ylno eht saw tahT
.thgin taht sruoh dna sruoh rof 0020 saw tI
?dad ym tuoba uoy gnillet em rebmemeR
.txen eb ot dneirflrig sih tcepxe retteb d’eh
,uoy leef dna ,seye ruoy ni sthgil rieht tnuoc dluoc I dna thgin raelc dloc eht revo enohs srats eht erehw gnineve laer eno dah ylno ew ,dne eht nI
,tuo yad dna ni yad esuoh eht dnuora yal I neht dna ,dray rebmul eht ta yug a fo tuo hteet eht dekconk I
.daeh ym ni aedi eht eldarc ot
ot esle tahw wonk t’ndid I ,yrros m’I -gnitirw deppots I .ereht yeH     ***     ”.ueiD ed mon ,yug gnikcuf eht er’uoY
.ti fo thguoht uoy tahw em dlot reven uoy dna ,taht retfa tuo tog I ,lleW
.kcab meht gnidnes deppots uoy tub ,rebmemer ,sliame dna srettel uoy gnidnes tpek d’I -sraey rof uoy tuoba derednow d’I
eht em evig ot elttil a dehsilop dna
,nosaes yniar eht saw ti em dlot yeht ,devirra ew nehW
.em fo dloha tog mom ruoy nehT
uoy gniveirg fo sraey eht gnihsaw
noonretfa eht fo eulb tsal
.noziroh eht fo keehc eht sessik gnineve sa
,eson elttil ruoy dna
,srae ruoy fo tnac eht
yojne esaelP   .ytiniffaruF no
.ewa ni dna ,diputs yrev tlef dna ,nrob erew uoy erehw ecalp eht was I
.uoy ni taht was I dna tnatropmi enoemoS
.yawa ti gniworht dna pu tihs siht gnillab peek I esuaceb dapeton fo tuo nur ot gniog m’I diarfa
ijustihoK yb ”uoY rebmemeR I“
.ksam ruoy no sgnaf ehT
.dnuora lla delip wons eht htiw
?ytrap yadhtrib s’eikciD rebmemer uoy ,yawyna dnA
.yas
,revoyal fo sruoh eerht tsal eht roF
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,ereht thgir deppots evol-yppup eht llA
.elpoep ta deppans I ,hteet dewohs I ,sgniht ffo dnim ym teg ot degnarra setad htiw naem tog I
.devres I retfa dna erofeB
.5-E edam uoy yhw s’tahT
?uoy rof krow eht lla did srae gib ruoy hguoht neve seissup erew ew su gnillet uoy dna
.won sduolc gnirehtag eht ees dluoc uoy hsiw I
.thgin yb sdray rebmul gnidraug detrats dna atosenniM ot kcab emac I ecnO
.uoy ni ecneloiv a saw ereht ,yawyna dnA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
neht deb sih fo tuo uoy ekil pmirhs a peek t’ndluoc eh fi taht dias dna tsehc sih no doots dna dnuorg eht ot etavirp eht werht uoy woh
.liat dna sgel ruoy fo erutsop eht
siht ekil ezeerb a
,nwolc ynapmoc eht saw I denialpmoc syawla uoY
,yenom fo tnuoma laitnatsbus a em tfel dah uoy dias ehs tub
.kcis tlef I retfa gninrom eht dna ’mih s’taht ,mih s’taht‘ dias
,uoy tuoba gnikniht
.kniht I ,oot evael ot detnaW
,swap ruoy ot trap taht tfel uoy tuB
.pu em kcip ot deirt rehtorb ym ,taht retfa ,lleW
,lanimret tropriA lanoitanretnI eraH’O eht ni siht gnitirW
,dnas gnilriws eht dima thgir
,neht litnU     .dnal rehtona fo
.raeh ot detnaw uoy gniht eht dias I sa enim tsniaga ydob llams ruoy leef
,uoy dnif lliw I kniht I dnA
.duorp dna tnedifnoc dna hgih
?rof tiaw annog uoy erew tahw dna ,pu nevig ro ,thgiew no tup d’I
eht ni ,srats eht woleb dna aes eht evoba tniop a ot tuo
.emit drah a saw tahT
,em dlot evah dluow uoy hsiw I
.yats d’I .og d’uoY
,ysatnaf ym dekil I naht retteb ti dekil I
,ti no pirg a teg dluoc reven I .gnignol a dnA
,gnihtemos dnatsrednu t’ndid uoy nehw srae ruoy tnac d’uoy woH
lrig nworb ym ,uoy no dna ,slraep no ti dneps d'I
.ssa ym tib evah dluow uoY
uoy fo erom saw ereht esuaceb
.gnihtyna enod evah dluow I dna
.ti tuoba dab saw I dna raey a koot tI
,swen eht no gnitteg dna dnas eht ni dnuora gnihcram dna evila dna pu erew uoY .evila erew uoY
.tuo tog reven uoy neht tub ,tuo tog uoy nehw pu teem d’ew dias uoY
.swen eht revo emac uoy fo erutcip taht nehT
,edarg driht ni uoy tib drofelkcaH kereD retfa sevlow detsurt reven uoy dna
.detceles neeb d’uoy taht nwod emac redro eht ,retal htnom A
erehw dnuorg railimaf no niaga kcab
,taht ekil pu dne ot diarfa neeb syawla d’I
.nug derih a gnieb ni yenom retteb tsuj s’ereht sseug I tub
.gnitirw neeb ev’I
.dratsum detah uoy woh rebmemer I
.emas eht lla deneppah ti tub ,aedi diputs A
”uoY rebmemeR I“ saw sihT.uoy rebmemer I
.ot nwod sliob ti tahw s’taht sseug I     .naeJ syas ”.erreug al tse’C“ .erew su fo rehtien ro ,saw I ro ,erew uoy ebyam
wodahs niar eht ni em rof gnitiaw
.egnahc laer a ekam ot ,enarbmem eht hguorht sserp
,ereht ffilc hgih a revo tuo gnikool m’I won dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
’dneirf tseb‘ ruoy saw I taht dias ehs tnecca kciht reh ni dna
.em dewercs d’uoy gnikniht dna
,retniw fo elddim eht ni hcrop s’retsis elttil ym no tuo dessap I
.niar gnikaerb eht ees dluoc uoy hsiw I
sdleif neerg eht ni tlep ot tlep ,eslup rof eslup
,thgin taht mom ym dellac I
.nur evah dluow I
.ezilanretni t’ndid dna ,draeh ylno d’uoy gnihtemos nialpxe ot dah ro
,decudorp-ssaM .dedlom noitcejni ,demaerd I ,erew uoy fo nees d’I strap eht dna ,od
,dloc werg uoy esuaceb ton
,uoy rof gnitiaw saw I taht gniwonk ,trofmoc elttil a uoy evig yeht diD
.taeh eht tsniaga yltneg srits llits efil erehw
ot pu eb ot dedeen yeht yaw eht ni pu selkcah ym nettog evah dluow ti dna tlusni na flah ti edam evah dluow uoy tuB .od ot dna ,ees ot ,eb ot em ni erom saw ereht em dlot evah dluow uoy ebyam
,niatpac maet ,erew uoy ereht dna ,trops s’erovinrac a si raw syas syawla enoyrevE
flesruoy dloh ,taht ekil tresed eht tsniaga flesruoy etteuohlis dluow uoy ylnO
,srab yag fo edistuo sthgif dekcip I
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.gnidnes saw I serutcip eht ni tniop emos ta detacinummoc saw taht ebyam dna epahs fo tuo saw I
.eroda I htrae siht no evol rehto on s'ereht roF
.yruxul fo noisserpmi
?tog sthgin eht dloc woh rebmemeR
.gniht a yas t’ndid dna ti dellems ehs dna ,denoitats eninac rehto ylno ehT
,god.ecioveht ta
,lleW .diputs syawla erew uoy syas dna
.uoy rof tiaw ot duorp saw I
.daeh ym fo tuo dedeen I dna
.dlrow eht ssorca lla uoy fo sotohp htiw
,efil siht htiw enod ma I retfa ,yad enO
,ebyam ,ssa ym ni ti ees dluoc uoY
?uoy hcaer neve yeht did --meht daer uoy diD
.tniop emos ta ymra eht tiuq d’uoy nwonk ev’dluohs I
.uoy gniggeb saw I neht dna ,yrgna saw I neht dna ,emit gnol a lained ni neeb d’I .sdnamed fo tol a saw tI
uoy ta gnikool syawla saw I dna
.evael ot dah uoy esuaceb tub
,won ereht tuo uoy ees tsomla nac I
,yad yb sdleif eht gnissorc dna thgin ta srevir eht gnimmiws flow lacidem a si ohw
.dnik yrev erew stnerap ruoY
.wonk ot dah uoy oS .ylsuoires gnihtyna koot reven I taht
was eW .nam reerac a erew uoy wenk I
,pu em dellac ehS
,em ta gnikool syawla erew uoy ,seissup elpoep gnillac erew uoy nehw os
,ijustihoK yb ”uoY rebmemeR I“
.lla ta klat t’ndluoc I neht I dna
,doohdlihc ruoy tuoba em dlot uoy nehw
em tel uoy sgniht eht ,enod d’ew sgniht eht ,dias d’ew sgniht ehT .diputs tlef I
.t’ndid uoy fi ko s’tI
,sisnemiS sinaC rednu dekram eman nwo ym dna
.yug taht fo tuo tihs eht taeb I ,doG     .retfa emac taht
,erutsop ruoy ni ti was ,ecaf ruoy ni ti
,yob atosenniM a saw I
naelc yltsom saw daD
.uoy roF .uoy morF
.sseug I ,emit ym detsaW .deirrow dna deirrow I
.raeh ot detnaw I tahw yas d’uoy nehT
.em ta dekool uoy ,dehgual
.detnaw I tahw dna ,su tuoba yas ot saw ereht tahw dias I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.romra cimarec evitalba eht dna ,nug ruoy dna liat ruoy ,os tsuj
.sgnidliub ssalg hgih ni sdrac gniyalp dna sragic gnikoms
.tsrif ta ti rof uoy emalb t’ndid I
.tinu tsal ruoy morf regit eht ,naeJ tem I
,knub mottob eht rof thgin tsrif taht thguof uoy woh rebmemer I
.ecaf ym ni dehgual yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
emit eht ta lagel t’nsaw top tub
,taem nam hsipluv nacirfa-htron fo sehcni-ruof-teef-ruof rof gnitiaw saw I taht ,sevlesmeht kcuf dna og ot nwot otni emac ohw semalf dlo eht dna dray rebmul eht ta yug dega-elddim taht dna rab eht ta sedud eht dlot dna htiaf ruoy tpek I taht gniwonk
,wonk I ,diputs saw ti dnA
.rehguot em detnaw uoy gniwonk dna
.hpargotohp sih morf ,yug gnikcuf eht er’uoY“ .dias eh ”edrem ed ledroB“     ?em was eh nehw dias eh tahw wonk uoy oD
.flesmih rof deracs tog eh drah os llef I kniht I .emit eht ta
,ni pu werg I eno eht ekil tserof krad emos ni uoy gnidnif fO
?scip htaehs eht ekil uoy diD
.looc dna suoiretsym mees uoy edam ti tub
,stfihs lanrutcon dekrow llits I ,loohcs hsinif t’ndid I .yzal nettog d’I
.su rof yenom hguone dah uoy nehw tuo teg d’uoy dias yehT
.su rof kool ot derac ydobon erehw
.tnaegres ,yawa em yrrac lliw
.eb dluoc I ynnuf woh wenk uoY
diulf dna hself dna ruf eht lla rednu deirub
em dnuof yeht dna
,gninnigeb eht ta yaw
,ssarg dna stoor eht no uoy nip dna nwod uoy esahc dluoc I
,rettel drow-elgnis a ,pit-rae na em wohs ot tsuj uoy htiw gnidaelP
.deveiler saw I kniht uoy ebyaM
.wonk uoy ’,oot uoy evol I‘ rof gnikool saw I
.ynnuf saw ti thguoht syawla I tub ,thgif taht fo esuaceb dekup ew litnu spal nar lla eW
.uoy rebmemer I     ciryL hsirI dlO-
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.em ot gniklat t’nerew uoy tub
.emit gnol a ni edam ev’I ekoj tsrif eht s’taht ekil leef I
.larenuf eht dah eW
.evila llits ,tresed eht fo daehdog elbicnivni
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,sburhs tnacs dna htrae dna dnas fo dleif tsav a ssorca gnizag
.ekoj a s’tahT … .llat gnidnats
,liat ruoy dleh uoy woh ynnuf saw ti thguoht I
,traeh dednuow ym no gnihtaerb dniw siht fo gnileef eht wenk uoy hsiw I
.setteragic sih ekoms tonnac dna ,enoretsotset regit war fo teef neves tsomla s’eh esuaceb nwod dna pu gel sih gnicnuob ,won em ot txen gnittis s’eH
,enola gniklaw tnew ew sa neve ,ti tuoba deirrow I tub ,derac ro deciton uoy taht wonk t’nod I
.sseug I ,yug gnikcuf emos tsuj saw I .uoy erew uoY
.srettel gnidnes deppots I neht dnA
?dnas eht rebmemeR
,gnikoms elfir ruoy fo lerrab eht ,gnidnuow lla dna htaed lla tsniaga deromra
?pu erusaem dluoc meht fo eno a ton dna
,taht revo yttihs tog tsomla I dna
.ti fo nuf hsixof eht rof deyalp d’uoy taht ,sseug I ,ekoj fo dnik emos saw I tahT
-liat ym htiw ti demarf I
seidnI tsew eht ni s'taht yenom eht lla I dah woN
.pots ot uoy ecnivnoc ot enoyna rof knurd oot erew tub htiw yalp ot gnihton dah dna ,rekop ni strohs ruoy tsol uoY
erohs nacirfA eht fo dlog eht I dah rO
uoy ekil neeb evah dluow tI