.snoitseuq tsegnarts eht deksa ehs semitemoS
pmac a ni rehtegot deldduh dah yeht
seirujni sih fo tnuoc tsol dah eH
.rood gnisolc eht ta
woh ta dekcohs saw
a…enustiK a ,dehcaorppa
.seye reh ni sraet eht edih ot elba regnol on
gninrom eht fo sruoh ylrae eht yB
,sresuort sih rof gnilbmuf
”?sdneirf ew era ,naem I“
,rehto eht ot ti denoitnem dah rehtien dna
hturt eht reh dlot dah eH
,emit gnol a enog neeb dah eH
.erawa ton erew yeht gnidneterp
.dednetni eh erofeb derewsna dah
.gnisuma dnuof eh flesti ni hcihw
”…thgiN a rof ylnO fI“
,gniwols saw eh wenk eh
,liat elgnis a ylno dah ehs yhw
,ecarbme sih denruter dna dexaler ehS ”…uoy gnieb roF“
emoh morf yawa yenruoj tsrif reh saw ti detcepsus eH
,nrevat a ni moor thginrevo na detner eH
.ecnatpecca dengiser a htiw egnahc eht degdelwonkca ehs tub ,noitanitsed dennalp rieht ton saw siht
ydob reh tuoba suoicsnoc fles tahwemos demees ehs
.tsal eht eb ton ylekil tsom
.yhtrowtsurt eb ot roteirporp eht wenk dna erofeb desu dah eh eno
.…“ ,gninetsil saw ehs taht wenk eh hguoht
.mih ot tnatropmi os saw taht yhw
,ratla eht nopu drows sih dial
,eniuneg dna mraw ,delims eh ,”ecin tub ,egnarts saw tI“
,emanresu emas eht rednu ytiniffAruF ta dnuof eb nac ehs
.yawa raf yrev dna
,teews dna hgih saw eciov reh dna tnecca lausunu na dah ehS
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”…nagirroC uoy knahT“
.degnahcnu deniamer syawla yeht wohemos
.emit siht ylmrif erom ,mih dleh ehs
?namow a htiw nial reve eh daH
.daeh reh gnikahs ,yawa dekcab ehs tub
,evol edam yeht erofeb ,smrof dekan srehto hcae derolpxe dna denimaxe yeht yldeirruhnu
---------------------- .syawla rof dna ecno ,niaga rehtegoT
.dlrow eht yb detanicsaf os eno dnA
enam yditnu na saw
.noitaerc reh gnirud wons denetihw fo tav eht otni deppid saw ehs sa deppirg dah sdog eht erehw saw taht
,ereht gnidnats saw nosrep A
,desuma neeb ton dah ehS
---------------------- ”...eromreverof dna woN“
”?yap uoy did ecirp tahW“
,elims a htiw derewsna eh
,dnah reh ni koob a htiw dnuof eb yllausu nac ohw ,gnireB yb
,ytisnetni egnarts a htiw ezag sih dleh
ew…won dna ereh tub.…“
,reh ta yldnof delims eH
.traeh eltneg sih fo taeb eht tlef
,deb eht ffo depmuj ehS
lliw tub ,ysatnaF otni yarof tsrif reh si siht
.ylisword derumrum ehs ,”…ecin sleef tahT“
”?enustiK a gnieb ekil uoy did…oS“
dna mrif saw rewsna sih tey
.thgilnoom revlis ni deniltuo ylprahs
,deksa ehs ,”?tahw roF“
.saw ylurt ehs ekil-lamina
,gniog saw siht erehw erusnu ,kcab yal eH
,erofeb decneirepxe reven dah ehs gnihtemos ,deb eht no dezod
taht tas eh yaw drawkwa eht morf detcepsus ehS
,reh morf gnidih saw eh tahw derednow yltnelis
spahrep saw hcihw
reh deksa ecno dah eH
.eh naht regnuoy ylniatrec saw ehs tub saw ehs dlo woh niatrecnu saw eh
.sdrow niatrec gnicnuonorp elbuort dah elzzum reh ot eud hguoht lworg eninimef a htiw ekops ehs
!riaf ton s’tI !riaf ton s’tI“
.liat a fo bun a deniater osla dah eh
.ti tuoba reh esaet ot dekil eH
.diarfa ylneddus ,deksa ehs ,”?nagirroC“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
yawa dedaf evah ot demees sehca sih ,t’ndid eh ylurT
.tpecca ot demees dah ehs eno
,”!analA t’nod…t’nod ,analA“
.tnemmoc ot etilop oot yllareneg erew elpoep tub
;deniamer sracs dlo sih teY
,rewsna t’ndid ehS ”…siht ekil yats tonnac I“
,neeb dah yeht sa prahs sa ton snoitcaer
.tnecsemut gniworg flesmih tlef eh
.woble sih ot tsomla gnihcaer ruf
,trihs sih dekoohnu ehs ylwolS
.thgis nommoc a morf raf erew
.namuh ton enoemos
,seye reh hcaer ot deliaf ti tub
.tsehc erab sih no swap llams htiw doots ,ediw ti daerps
reh ot deil dah eh taht mih derehtob dah ti tuB
,dnal siht ni erehwyreve tsomla erew snamuH
reh dlot ecno dah eH
tsap reh tuoba klat ot tnatculer demees ehS
.gel tfel raer reh no kcalb fo hctap a morf trapa
,raelc erew sgnidnuorrus reh seye reh oT
,drows-lles a saw eH
.elims niatrecnu na htiw ,seye sih otni dekool ehs sa derevihs ehS
,deb eht ffo ylthgil tpael ehS
”.dnim t’nod I yllaer“
,dnah ekil-wap a reh gniwohs
?tsrif emoc egaugnal rieht fo taht ro elpoep reh fo eman eht did
,yltneg mih delzzun
,traeh reh deppirg raef fo llihc ehT .deunitnoc eh
…wenk ehs wohemos dnA
.segnih delionu fo kaerc eht htiw ,nepo gnuws rood eht sa esirprus ni depmuj ehs…terf ot nugeb
”,enif stI“ ”…yrros m’I“
,enola tfel eb ot yppahnu neeb dah ehS
,regral yldekram hguoht
.niaga deksa ehs ,”?nagirroC“
,hturt eht ekops eh rof ,raelc
,peels detsuahxe na otni nellaf dah ehs sa
thgin nezorf drah a no retniw tsaL
elims ot detpmetta ehS
.raef sih hguorht ecnaifed
.revocer ot kciuq ssel ydob sih
.eussi eht sserp ton dluohs ehs desnes dah tub erom ksa ot dekil evah dluow ehs wenk eH
.kaeps ot flesmih gnirb etiuq ton dluoc eh demees ti tey
,mih sdrawot reh werd
,dednim eh taht toN
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,dehcaorppa eh ylwolS
.noitanalpxe tcerroc eht rof nam denrael a tuo thguos dah eh dna
.hserfa efil ecneirepxe
.mih erofeb gninrub erifpmac a
.ylivaeh llef ehs dna ffo reh dehsup eh
xof yranidro na morf ecnereffid laer ylno ehT
.nam llams a ton saw eh dna
”analA gninrom dooG“
,reh rof dehcaer dna seenk sih ot tog eh
redlo nettog dah eh sa dna
.enustiK dna namuH ,riap ddo na
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,gnireB yb
,reh fo tnorf ni tlenk eH
,esolc nworg dah yehT
.meht fo ynam dnim reven
,gniK sih fo ymra eht ni thguof dah eh ecnO .yranecrem a
,lufthguoht dna teiuq demees dah ehs
tnarongi raeppa ot dekil ton dah eH
,delims dna mih fo tnorf ni deppots ehS .deksa eh
,raey a tsomla rof snoinapmoc gnillevart neeb dah yeht
.srednic gniwolg ot nwod denrub
,rehtruf gnihtemos ksa ot gniog saw ehs demees tI
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ti tlef eh semitemos tey ,nam dlo na morf raf saw eH
,eert a tsniaga kcab sih htiw dexaler tas nagirroC gniraelc tserof eht ni
.htuom railimafnu sih ni drawkwa
,ti desu dah eh seY
.tpels ylurt reven tub
,tfel eh erofeb yletsahc reh dessik eH
naf noitciF-ecneicS emit gnol A
.thgis sih morf yawa gnihtolc degnahc syawla dna
,meht gnisu drawkwa saw ehS
.ynapmoc s’rehto hcae ni esae ta
.niap derebmemer fo sotnemem
,rewol dehcaer ehS
hguoht syad tnecer nI
,sdnah namuh sa suortxed sa ylraen ton gnieb
.niaga pu rettam eht thguorb ton dah ehS
,moor gniniojda eht morf ni deklaw eh sa llef traeh reh
.hsiugna htiw detsiwt ecaf
”…thgiN a rof ylnO fI“    yojne esaelP
,”neppah yam siht ekil gnihtemos em dlot sserecroS eht sediseB“
.ti desu dah eh ,seY ?ti desu eh daH
.saw yllautca ehs naht yldlrow dna erutam erom raeppa ot gniyrt ,gnuoy saw ehS
,noitamrifnoc erew taht seye eht saw ti tey dna ,tnecs yb mih wenk ehS
,reh ot denruter noitnetta sih thguoht eht tA
.yhw dootsrednu eh erus ton saw eh
;stnemnroda rehto dna kaolc reh tuohtiw reh nees reven dah eH
.nwonk dah eh lla saw ti tub ,yawa drows sih tup ot dehsiw dna ti rof etsat eht tsol dah eh hturt nI
denrut eh sa yawa detrad dah ehS
…depoh dah ehs wohemoS
.dehctaw eh nehw ti ekil t’ndid dna
,rae reh ni derepsihw eH
.mih tsurt ot reh deksa eh nehw detpecca dah tub
.nwod daeh reh htiw gniklaw
dehsiw eh taht hcus
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,seye reh hguorht ees dluoc eh
,naelc liat elgnis a gnipeek elbuort hguone dah ehS
.ecnelis otni kcab despal dah ehs tub
”?sdneirf ew era…rroC“
,rednow ni seiks eht gnihctaw neeb dah ehS
,trihs sih detfil dna denrut eH
?eh dluoc enustiK kaeps t’ndluoc eh lleW
.erofeb ereht neeb reven dah taht
,niaga esir ot tnew dna
”…rroC gninrom dooG“
.eert eht tsniaga niaga  kcab denael dna
,edis reh no yldrawkwa yal ehs sa flesreh desiar ehS
,yad nmutua gnol a retfa ksud saw tI  gnireB yb
,gninaem yna dleh regnol on emiT
,”…yrros m’I ,analA“
,stnetnoc sti dna ti fo hcni yreve gninimaxe
”.hguone tnemyap saw erised erup a dias ehS“
,daeh reh koohs ehs tub kaeps ot edam eH
,kaolc reh devomer neht
;kcab tsniaga ylleb
,ylthgils detfihs eh sa gnihtemos derettum ehS
,”?syawla uoy rof siht ekil ti sI“
,tpew ehs sa koohs mrof llams reH
pihsdneirf rieht ni ylrae ecnO
,rediw werg elims siH
,tsomtfel eht ffo dellup dna
.sih tuoba suoiruc saw tub
,xof yadyreve na sa hcum os gnihton ekil dekool ehs ecnaraeppa nI
,tuo ylraen saw erif eht taht deciton eH
.nruter ni erusserp eltneg a tlef dna dnah reh dezeeuqs eH ”…rehtegot era
.ssenraen reh ,tnecs reh morf
,ekawa dekrej ehs sa swodniw deniatruc eht hguorht gnimaerts saw thgil gninroM
,selballysonom ni ylno gnikaeps
.ti gnilio tas eh sa drows sih ta gnikool reh deciton dah eh
”…evol rof ti od I“
,”sdneirf er’ew esruoc fO“
,ytisoiruc nepo na deyalpsid ehS
,skool suoiruc emos deviecer yehT
,erofeb dekan reh nees reven dah eH
derednow tey ,dalg saw eH
enal yrtnuoc a gnola gniklaw neeb dah yehT
;mih ot denrut ylneddus dah ehs nehw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ylthgit reh dleh
,deirrow nworg dah ehs
.mih ot flesreh dehcatta dah ehs yhw
,snoitseuq reh yb desirprus neeb dah eH
.draeb fo htworg yad wen sih gnihsurb sreksihw
,syad gniwollof eht ni emas ton erew sgnihT
hgual a htiw derewsna eh
.sniap dna sehca detalumucca sih morf noitisop elbatrofmoc erom a dnif ot gniyrt
,mih deppots ehs niaga ,”…analA“
,teef reh ot esor ehS
…yletanoissap ,yltneg ,ylwols
,sdnah devolg sih gnihctaw reh deciton eH
,nwot lacol a ni od ot ksat a dah eh taht reh dlot eH
drow eht ,derewsna eh ,”…analA“
,reh naht tliub yllufrewop erom dna regral saw eh…elam
,sseltsil dna llud
.lufhtuoy dna gnorts tlef eh dna
.eno siht ekil hcum
.deirram ton saw eh
meht neewteb nworg dah ecnatsid A
,derewsna eh ,”gnihtoN“
.noinapmoc gnillevart a evah ot ecin saw ti
…eno sa gnitaeb straeh owt ,tpels yehT
.”retteb tol a uoy dnatsrednu ylniatrec I“
rednow ni erats ot reh gnivael
,mih tsniaga debbur ehS .”…uoy wohs em teL“
,rehtegot yal yeht sdrawretfA
dedisbus ylwols dah sbos reH
”…thgiN a rof ylnO fI“ saw sihT
,mrof wen sih morf snoitasnes egnarts eht yb demlehwrevo
,nosaer a pu edam dah os dna
,oN ?deirram eh saW
reh revo ylevitcetorp yal gelerof sih
.cilobmys tsael ta ro ,htym a saw gniht sliat elpitlum eht taht denialpxe
,niatrecnu dna demlehwrevo elttil a saw ehs desnes dna
,seye sih desiar eH .kcab deppets
.loop kcor nepo na ni dehsaw eh sa gnihctaw reh thguac ecno dah eh tuB
,erow ylerar yrev eh gnihtemos
.llacer ot dekil eh naht semit erom
.emit gnol a rof toN
.yrellag reh ni krowtra denoissimmoc dna seirots htob gniwohs
,deudbus dna teiuq saw ehs
.seye reh ni kool egnarts a ,mih deppots ehs tub esir ot edam eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.stoob sih no gnillup nageb dna riahc ybraen a no tas eh sa dehctaw
,tsehc sih tsniaga daeh reh gnitser
,moor eht decap dah ehs
”…era ew ylniatrec lleW“
”analA uoy knaht dluohs ohw I si tI“
.ruf tfos reh hguorht sregnif sih nar eh yltnesba
,pu reh derehtag eH
,derevihs eh trap sih roF
,rednow mih edam ti hguoht ,tniop riaf a saw tI
.edisa ti deppord
.swap tnorf reh no sbmuht llams eht dna riah ekil-namuh fo
.ruf neklis no ruf neklis
.ydob sih otno ylluferac deppets
.thgil saw ehs erehw krad
.edis dna pih sih no ssenkrad yklis fo hctap rehtruf a
,moor eht ni enoemos saw erehT
,mih sdrawot devom neht
,hgiht sih tsniaga gnitser daeh reh htiw yal analA dneirf siH
,srewoP eht erofeb doots eh sa delbmert eH
”?rehtegot eb ew t’nac yhW
…retfa emit gnol a rof ekawa yal eh
.os delkniwt srats eht yhw deksa
oga gnol saw emit taht tub
,ylthgil ksa ot detpmetta
,etihw tserup eht fo ruf dna
,erar yltcaxe ton elihw ,senustiK dna ,ecar tnanimod eht
.deniwtne sdnah dewap rieht htiw
,eenk sih ot pu emac sredluohs reh gnidnats nehw
.noitanicsaf dewa ni mih dnuora decap ehs ,”…uoy ylurt si tI“
ylthgit reh dleh ,mih sdrawot reh dellup
.desaelp demees dah ehs dna
seye enipluv eulb elap dah ehS
,dehgual dna yllufyalp mih dettab dah ehs