.htaerb peed a koot I  ”.yrroS“
.gat eman ym fo espmilg a thguac ehS ”…hu ,uoy knahT“
.shtnom ni daD ot deklat t’ndah I
.knird a koot I sa tis taht tel I  ”.nalp ym s’tahT“
.worbeye na desiar ehS
dednuos ,eltsihw railimaf a ,eciov siH ”?yeliR“
— floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.dnabsuh ym fo erutcip gnignah a koohs dniw eht ,weivraer eht woleB
.ytinrete nwo sti detibahni gnir htruof ehT
thguoht a nehT .reh ta evaw ot detrats I  ”!yeliR ,em ot tol a snaem sihT !hcum os uoy knahT“ .erom ecno em ot deddon dna
:hsurb kciht eht ni reh was I
”.dnalni rehtruf seinoloc tsol rehto noillim a dnif d’uoy—lleH
,seiceps-ssorc nevE
”nwotemoH ruoY nI m’I“   yojne esaelP
.htap tcerroc eht otno kcab nrut ot gnitiaw tas I
.em ta decnalg anuL
.live saw ytilauxesomoh thguoht moM“
.erutcip sih ta decnalg ehS
”.sdneirfyob wef tsal ym htiw tuo dekrow t’ndah sgniht ecnis ,neht stohs fo tol a gnitoohs saw I
.revo depeep I nehw niaga gniward dna wodniw eht tuo gnirats saw anuL ”?pag ega eht htiW“  ”.esion
.mih ekil eb ot em gnihcaet—
.daeha ciffart fo noitargim ssam a gnitpmorp ,neerg denrut thgil noitcesretni ehT
”.sllac sih gninruter deppots I os ,efil fo tuo sgniht tnereffid detnaw ew kniht I
”.lairetam lanigiro rof gnikool neeb ev’I dna
.emoh rieht depahs ytitnedi taht woh dna
.egap reh ssorca tpews etihparG ”.ym hO“
.wap ym ni gnar enohp eht sa thgil eht ta pu elip ciffart gnihctaw
.kcurt liam eht fo kcab eht morf delaes gnol rettel a ekil daer gniward eht
.tiusrup ym htiw pu thguac noitatiseH  ”?ohW“
?etelpmocni tlef sraey neetriht esoht evah tuB“
”?ynoloc eht tuoba wonk uoy did dnA“
.yks ytic eht revo sruoloc fo snoillim fo atsiv a dniheb gnivael ,weiv morf enog saw nus ehT
.gnihtyna yas t’ndid anuL  ”.reverof tsal ll’ti naem t’nseoD“
.pots ym ta er’ew erofeb em rof esle gnihtemos od dluoc uoy fi gnirednow saw I
”?eitsop ,em rof rettel a toG“
er’uoY“ .knurt ytpme eht ta kcab dereep dna
,rekcepdoow gniga na ,doots eh erehT
.hteet reh tsniaga licnep eht deppat ehS ”.ylsuoivbo
”.deifsitas eb reven lliw ytisoiruc ym dna
.ti fo edis eht no dekrap srac yb tfel enal-flah eht gnitagivan ylluferac ,daor eht no dexif seye ym tpek I
,tsehc reh ot daphcteks reh dehctulc ehS ”.emoH“
”?aera eht tuoba uoy llet reve eh diD“  ”.flesruoy tiuS“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.smra sih ni efiw mussop
”,mussop a er’uoy dnA“  ”.llewoL“
”,tcejorp ygoloporhtna nA“
dehcterts ehs nehw kcurt eht hguorht
.dlo edaced a tsael ta otohp tcatnoc a saw eliforp sih gninildaeH
”.taht rof yrros ton m’I“
.reh ta delwocs I
ereht t’nsi ecnedive eht taht
.ylknalb em ta kcab derats ehS
,stnediser ynam ot klat ot ecnahc a nettog yllaer t’nevah I ,ees uoY
ega reh eciwt ylraen enoemos ot yas ot gniht suoiruc a
.sgub fo riohc eht htiw derrup enigne ehT
dnim reh ni hctiws a deppilf noitseuq ym fi sa ,taht no detcelfer ylneddus ehS
.bruc eht ediseb revo dellup I
”.rood eht ta krelc on s’erehT
”.yademos tpoda ot evol d’I ?em rof tuB“
.swap koohs ew ,ofni tcatnoc gnippaws retfA
.depoord srae s’anuL
,enohp ym rof dnuora dehsif I
”.ereh ralupop er’yeht ,lleW“
”.esnes sekam tahT“
.rebmun desunu-gnol a nopu demool yllanif I litnu
ksa dluow eh wenk I
.gnitirw tpek tsuj ehs ;tcatnoc eye ekam t’ndid ehS
.hcaorppa rehtona deirt dna taorht ym deraelc I
”?etuor s’esle enoemos rof nwot tfel uoy yhw ksa I yaM“
.ti revo etiuq s’daD kniht t’nod I“
koobhcteks a dleh ehS
.kaolc detnecs-breh reh fo smra eht rednu deggurhs ehs dna yawa denrut seye reh ,yllaniF
.redluohs etisoppo sih no dnah a gnitser xer
.reviled ot eerged a deen t’ndid I dna ,oga edaced a
yb deklaw snairtsedep fo riap A
.syad eerht ni eud saw efiw siH“
.anuL ta decnalg I ,skcab ruo ta nuS
,eciffo latsop eht morf nwod skcolb elpuoc a
.leehw eht fo rehtael eht revo sregnif ym nar I ,krims a htiW
.rood eht ta doots dna
,ekudnikood@ eldnah rettiwT eht yb krow sih wollof yam enO
pu em gninnam no tneblleh syawla saw eH
.steerts eseht gnivird flesym dnuof netfo I smaerd ni neve taht em otni deniargni os saw yromem elcsum ehT
”?emit ym etsaw yhW“
.tra reh morf yawa reh dellup taht
t’nod uoy ,wonk’y ,tuB
”.uoy rof tuo skrow taht epoh I“
.em ot ti dleh dna egap eht tuo deppir swap kciuQ
terreFekuD emanresu eht ro
”.ereh nrob t’nsaw I“
.elttil a delkcarc enil eht esuaceb
.hA“ .detatiseh anuL
.sehcnarb mlap hguorht deretlif thgilnus gniyD
.kcurt liam ym ta dereep ehS
.dap reh no gnihtemos elbbircs ot licnep reh rof dehcaer ehS
”.od nac I tahw ees ll’I“
.mottob eht ta gnittis spord elpuoc tsal eht tub gnihton gnitsat
.tseretni otni esor nworf digir reH
.dereffo I ”,tohs a htrow saw weivretni ehT“
”.kcab s’rehtorb sih no nwot ot kcab ti edam ylnO
.elims mraw s’ziuL yb dehctam
.daor eht no tas selcihev rehto oN
”.staes regnessap dah skcurt yreviled wonk t’ndid I“
.pmaws eht tuoba snoitseuq elpuoc a uoy gniksa flesym epat ot ekil d’I os
.noitazilaer ym ta ffo deliart I
”?txetnoc fo tuo htrow taht s’tahw dnA
”.tuo emac I retfa ecnamor tuoba em ot deklat reven eH
.kcen reh fo kcab eht dehctarcs anuL
.ylluftsiw em ta dekool ehs
”?ereh evil uoy oD“
.wollof I erus ton m’I“
?ziuL si redlo hcum woH“
.daeha segap elpuoc a gnilbbircs ,wap ni licnep ,daphcteks reh revo nwod daeh reh dah llits ehS
.epacsdnal a ekil kool t’ndid ti tub ,hcteks reh ees etiuq t’ndluoc I
.xelfer elpmis naht erom htiw evird ot
”.oN“  ”?retupmoC tuonS
koobhcteks reh dleh ehs sa kaolc reh naht rethgirb dewolg elims reH
.tresed eht ni sisao na gnidnif nam a ekil
.xer .T eht fo tiartrop gnikniw eht ta denediw seye reH ”!hO“
”.ytisrevinU nanreB morf tneduts egnahcxE
,bmuht ym rednu welf semaN
.yawa sraeythgil
.eirever ym fo tuo deppans I   .ti draeh I erofeb ti taeper ot dah ehS ”?yeliR“
”?neht ,tnemtsujda na fo tib a neeb ti saH“
”.gnitseretnI“ .dekramer ehs
.skcart reh ni reh deppots tahT
”.eno yrrac ot elba eb t’ndluow eh em sllet gnihtemoS
”.deid moM ecnis deklat t’nevah eW
.enog saw ti erofeb sthgildaeh s’rac ym fo maelg eht rednu rulb etihw a
,lleW“  ”.eno lacihposolihp eht em dellac uoY“ .dekrims ehS
.fo nrettap eht ezingocer t’ndid I sdrib owt—
.gniward reh ot nwod kcab denrut ehS
.swap ym daerps I ”.revo s’etuor ehT“
,pac ym htiw em werd ehS
”.dnim ym dessorc reven s’tahT“ .denworf I
”.ziuL“  ”?eman sih s’tahW“
;elpoep fo sdnik emas eht teem ,senituor emas eht evah eW“
erew yeht ohw fo stnemgarf—
”.ytic emaS“  .deksa I
meht ni yalp ot desu eh dias eH“  ”?sknurt rieht hguorht derob seloh htiw seert tnaig ehT“
.gnorw ti koot ehs fi ssakcaj latot a ekil dnuos d’I
”.evah I ecnedive eht lla si won ees ew tahW
”nwotemoH ruoY nI m’I“ saw sihT
.tfel I erofeb tuo mih deksa I
.tnereffid os s’erutluc ruoy...redrob
”?ereh nrob ziuL saW“
”?snoitanod mreps ynam woH“
.ecno ziuL tem daD“
”,ylimaf dnuof tuoba dias eb ot gnihtemos s’erehT“
.kaeps ot egaruoc eht pu retsum dluoc I litnu detiaw I
,tcejorp ym rof skcart oidua emos deen I
,egap eht no drow a ton htiw
.desolc seye ym htiw nwotnwod etagivan dluoc I enoyreve dlot I
.ecnatsid eht ni latipsoh eht ot pu nehT
.hcteks s’anuL ta nwod dekeep I
.delims dna sregnif reh dessorc anuL
”.esum ym rof erutan ot gninrut m’I
neve ,stnerapdnarg-taerg
.sesnes nwo ym htiw ynoloc tsol eht ni ekat ot deen I .pmaws peed ehT“
.dekcilf liat s’anuL
...fo gnikaepS“
”.enoemos fo em dnimer uoy ,wonk’Y“
”?uoy naht rellat hcum eh sI
tsuj uoY .sepolevne eht ni s’tahw tuoba kniht
.nedrag dlo s’mom ym morf dekcip srewolf ekil
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yrtne s’anuL tsap dellorcs dna tsil tcatnoc eht denepo
”,dad a eb ot tnaw uoy yhw ees I ,taht ekil sekoj htiW“
txetnoc fo yhs fi—su sllet tI“
uoy erus gnikam tsuJ“ .daeh ym koohs I
klawedis eht otno tuo deppets neht anuL
,ytic eht fo strikstuo eht no pu werg eh dias uoY
”.ti tuoba yppah oot t’nera stnerap reH
.deen I gnihtyreve evah I
”.uoy fo suoreneg s’tahT“
.thgil der a ot pu dellup I sa noisiv ym fo renroc eht ni ti thguac I
.ti gnihcteks m’I yhw s’tahT .gnihtoN“
”.tcejbus ruoy evah I naht flesym tuoba erom deklat ev’I kniht I .weivretni ruoy...fo
”!srood eht egrahc ton od esaelp dna su htiw gnidir rof uoy knahT .enil eht fo dne eht dehcaer sah tisnarT yeliR“ .gnas I ”!gnod ,gniD“  .revo
.gniggid tsuj naht erom yllaer s’tI“
.wodniw eht dnoyeb morf
.yltrohs delkcuhc I
.tuo tuc gnir eht ,daetsnI
”!kcab teg ot erus eb ll’I
.reporp pmaws eht evael ot egdirb a dessorc ew sa ecnelis ni tas eW
.egap reh ot kcab llef seye reH
”?thgir ,hguoht ,sraey neetrihT“
.decafruser reh was I tnemom eht morf em deggub taht
.ssap ti tel ot degrem I .raer ym no pu emac rac A
.tirehni ot deganam I sgniht emos erew ereht ,secnereffid ruo roF
sdrawot kcab em deddorp anuL noisiced eht yb deipuccoerp oot raf saw I
.nwod egap ,seenk reh no daphcteks eht deppord anuL  ”?ti sI“  ”.tnereffid
”.dlo sraey erew edor I sesub eht tub ,ziuL naht retal elihw elttil a loohcs ni saw I
saw tI  ”.reverof stsal gnihtoN“
.elpmaxe rof ,serots ruoy ekaT .yaw yreve nI“
”.moor gel on evah sesub ehT“
lapicinum dellac s’tahT“
.leehw eht dniheb tas dna ni deppets I
”?thgir ,rof si ffuts ’ynoloc tsol‘ siht tahw s’tahT“
”.em ot elbaulav si ti dnuora tliub serutcurts eht fo ecneirepxe ruoy tub
SPG eht ffo deppat I sa tol gnikrap eht otni dehsinav anuL
”.savnac reggib a deen annog er’uoy kniht I ,eiteewS“
.egelloc ot tnew reven I ;wonk I fi lleH“ .detrons I  ”.tsigoloeahcra na ton m’I“ .delkcuhc ehS
.suoicilam naht hsifles eroM
dekcohs syawla trap tahT“
.pac ym fo mirb eht dnuof sregnif yM
”.kcab uoy evird nac I“
.ecno ereh tuo tib tog elcnu yM“  ”?yllaeR“
.yltrohs delkcuhc I  ”.yrros m’I
retirw noitcif strops dna ecnamor reeuq a ,terreFekuD yb
”?ereh pu worg uoy did ,ffo trats oT .’taht‘ eht yeliR“
”?huh ,eerht staeb ruoh-na-flaH“
.pmaws eht fo hcterts lanif eht otni nrut ot leehw eht nups I
.gninrom taht desserd tog dna hteet ym dehsurb I nehw tuoba gniyrrow saw I ffuts fo dnik tahw rebmemer I
,mih rof pirt ssenisuB .lavitsef mlif a ta mih ot txen tas I nehw tem eW .uoL dah I ,lleW“
”.ereh morf setunim thgie tuoba pu werG .haeY“
.detrons ehS  .detcerroc I
.seye reh deworran ehs sa stekcop ym ni swap ym deffuts I
”.ot dnilb era stnediser gnolefil sgniht eht ees thgim tsuj uoY“
.pal reh otni delruc ti sa liat yhsub reh deiduts I ”.huH“
.loohcs reh raen denrut eciffo eht ot kcab htap ym deciton dna sgel ruo neewteb denoitats SPG eht ta yldi dekool I
”,eerht-ytnewt-
.raeh ot tnasaelp saw hgual mraw reH  ”.ecnetepmocni
”.hguoht ,siht hguorht teg ot tnaw llits I .ebyaM“
.ecnatropmi s’dlrow eht tnaem ti fi sa
.gninehtgnel swodahs eert eht deciton I sa sag eht no deppets I
”…rof retlehs eb ot desu hcihw ,sehcnarb eht ot sreddal evah swolloh emoS
.deppans aremac enohp reH   .delbmurg anuL
.gniteelf yad a gnikram
na sa taht tuoba deklat syawla stnerap yM
”.yrt dluoc ew tub ,lufpleh eb ll’I fi wonk t’nod I“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,tey ,wonk I seitic fo etamilc eht serahs ti esuaceb llewoL dekcip I
”.pmaws taht ni devil ohw elpoep eht ot—
,yb gnizzihw sraey
.peek ot uoy rof ti werd I“
.reh morf enohp eht koot I
.wodniw eht no woble ym dehcrep I ”?seiduts ruoy ni eussi na taht sI“  ”.llams
”.krad retfa suomonev gnihtemos otni nur uoy fi meht nioj ll’uoY“ .daeh ym koohs I
sduolc elprup fo spit eht dethgilhgih seuh egnarO .elgnuj etercnoc eht evoba wolley dewolg yks ehT
.stnerap ym morf trapa evil dluoc I taht flesym ot evorp ot detnaw I“  ”.wollof
.ecnatsid eht ni draobllib a ta gnirats ,dias I ”,haeY“
”.evif weivretnI .xis yluJ ,yadsruhT“
.em evag ehs kool detiecnocnu tsrif eht ebyaM
.tnew licnep eht kcaB
.txen eht srewsna elballys eno ,etunim eno evitaklaT
.eno rellams a neve rO
”?ereh yats ot tnenitnoc eht ssorca gnivom ekil ti saw tahw ,oS“
.yb deeps sehsub dna seert mlap eht gnihctaw ,wodniw edis ym ot detfird seye yM ”.teef elpuoc a dnA
”.ecalp rieht koot ohw esoht sa meht tuoba hcum sa tsuj s’tI .gnihtyrevE“
”,reganam hcnarb ecivres latsop lacoL“
.yad taht emoh deyats tsomla I drah os gniniar saw tI .ynnuf s’tI“
;yrots lluf eht llet t’nac I diarfa m’I semitemoS“
”?uoy llet taht seod tahw dnA“
.edanomel ym etacol ot rehto eht desu I ,leehw eht no gnitser wap a htiW ”.eganam ot rO
”?gniht elohw ehT“  ”.pmaws eht
”.won kcab klaw ll’I .yeliR“
.revo dellup dna ekarb eht no deppets I
...redrob eht morf sruoh owt yldrah gnieb rof
.T a doots mih dniheB
.egap eht ssorca sekorts gnol krow ot gniunitnoc ,egap suoiverp reh ot kcab deppilf ehs nehT ”.oN“
.noitseuq suoutpmuserp a fo tib A
.yaw eht yb ,anuL s’eman yM“
.taorht reh deraelc anuL
lerriuqs a sa won was I—erugif ehT
.drac ssenisub dna timrep ym gnidulcni ,steknirt dleihsdniw ym tcepsni ot desuap neht ,deddon ehS
.moor rehtona ot taerter ot dah I fi
ngis pots eht tsap denrut I sa pu em ekow SPG eht fo eciov citobor ehT
.ti fo trap s’tahT“
”?nwo ruoy evah toN“
.yb ssap kcurt rehtona dehctaw anuL
.taht revo derop dna wap eerf a htiw knird ym debbarg I
.llams si ezis elpmas yM“
.gnihtemos gnitirw saw ehs ekil dekool ti ,sregnif reh fo gnilggiw trohs eht morF
.tsohg a saw ehs ebyaM  ”.eid
.raef laitnetsixe
.daeh reh koohs anuL
”?seireviled ekam uoy hctaw I elihW“
yats ot em rof thgir eb t’ndluow ti thguoht I tub
.bulc hsauqs ym ni s’aidyL .edaced a ereh neeb s’ekiM ,lleW“
.elims sseldrow a erow mussop tnedifnoc ehT
.noitategev edisdaor nworgrevo fo edahs eht ni deprihc stekcirC
.denetaerht tlef eh derugif I dna ,drawkwa saw tI
,rehtegot swap reh deppat ehS
.sraey net deirram neeB“
.thgil ciffart gnimocpu na ta detniuqs I
.siseht reh rof ytic gniruobhgien a rof tfel dneirf yM“
.reh morf rewsna oN
,dewollof tsomla I
?emoh ot esolc oot tih ekoj ym diD
”?retaw gnirb uoy diD“
,thgil eht ta tnelis llef kcurt ehT
.thgiarts pu tas dna htaerb dleh ym fo og tel I .ti wenk I
.ytisrevinu eht ta ecnediser ni gnivil m’I ,oN“
rebmul ni krow ot desu daD“
,emyht fo dellems ehS
”.llacer I fi ,gniloohcs rof syaw a klaw ot dah llitS“  ”?thgir
.eid ro yawa evom ot meht dehsup rehtaew eht erofeb ereh devil ohw—
.gniog er’uoy erehw wonk
pmawS ehaL eht detisiv reve uoy evaH“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.deddon dna tnemom a rof revo taht thguoht ehS
”?reh htiw edis dad ruoy diD“
.daor eht ot kcab deggurhs I
.sreksihw ym dekorts I
”?ynoloc tsol a htiw od ot evah gniward ruoy s’tahW“
”.nwotemoh ruoy ni m’I .daD ,yeH“
.koobhcteks nepo reh ta nwod detniop saw tI
.thgil eht ta daeha deklaw snairtsedep fo puorg A
”.llams yllaer si mih fo erutcip ruoY
sih htiw duorp dna llat gninnirg
.thgin doog a evah uoY“
.draobhsad eht ot dennip sesnecil dna segap eht deltsoj ti litnu C/A eht pu denrut I
.flesruoy tuoba uoy deksa I“
.tnemom a rof liat reh hguorht dehsurb ehS
.dik a sa em llet ot desu dad ym esarhp a deticer dna delkcuhc I ”.gniht larutluc a tsuj ton s’tahT“
erew eh hguoht sa demees ti tub ,em hcaer ot tnenitnoc a dellevart langis ehT
.mussop eht fo ecaf dehcteks eht ta nwod deknilb I
,teiuq fo tnemom a retfA
.ecnatsid eht ni srewot nredom keels eht htiw dehsalc taht sgnidliub enots tneicna nopu evord ew sa deniamer ecnelis s’anuL
dellup dna supmac reh fo egnirf eht no yawsub a otni derenroc I
,ecneirepxe devil nwo ruoy tuoba snoitpmussa ekam ot toN“ .desum anuL
”.efil ym fo yrotcejart
.daor eht tih dna srorrim ym dekcehc I
.ria dimuh eht ni deniats taews erew kaolc reh fo smra ehT .dehcaorppa I sa pu em dezis lerriuqs ehT
”…ytic eht rof tuB
,evah I ekil pmaws eht deiduts t’nevah uoY“
.ytinas ’stneduts rieht rof drager on htiw rotatcid cimedaca emos yb dezinagro tcejorp a ylbaborP
.em ta denworf tsuj ehs tub ,elkcuhc a ro hgual a rof detiaw I
.elzzum ym dehctarcs I
”.maet a gnieb fo trap tsuj
?dlrow eht ni thguoht a tuohtiw dereviled uoy evah srettel evol ynam woH“
.sdik erew yeht nehw sdneirf sih htiw
”.egaugnal nwo sti skaeps dnal ehT
wodniw eht morf detfird ezag yM  ”?uoy tuoba tahW“
.ereht mih tuohtiw siht od ot detnaw I dna ,emoh ta em rof gnitiaw saw ziuL
”.ti evol lliw ymedaca eht erus m’I“ .dias I ”,dnuoforP“
.su neewteb wap a tuo tohs neht
,enohporcim eht otni deticer ehs
eht degnahc taht yad a otni dekcap sselgninaem os eb ot tuo denrut taht gnihtyrevE
.oot wollef redlo na gnitad s’ohw nanreB ni kcab dneirf a tog ev’I tuB“ .wap a devaw ehS ”.segareva rieht naht
.reh rof rood eht nepo dils I sa gnitniuqs ,kcurt liam eht ot kcab em dewollof ehS
.eciffo eht ot kcab yaw eht no ytic eht fo hcum ees t’ndid I
.tnemom a rof llits ylgnitnuah ,ezag ym dleh ehS  ”?tahw ekiL“
.flesti dnal eht tuoba yas nac uoy hcum os ylno s’erehT
.dewollof gnir dnoces ehT
.rekih-hctih flowerew
.sepyt ohcam tsilanoitidart esoht lla htiw
”?srekrowoc ruoy htiw esolc taht
?srebmun egnahcxe ew dluoC“
”.em ot erom gnihtemos htrow s’tI“
.weivraer eht morf gnignah erutcip eht ta deddon dna dehgual I
,kaolc reh fo gniw eht ni
.enohp reh no tuo yrtne tcatnoc knalb a dleh ehS ”…tpecxE
”.ni tif ehs naem t’ndid ereht devil ehs esuaceb tsuJ“
.yltcerid ziuL ot klat ot evol d’I dna sdael rof gnikool llits m’I
.pu ti detrats I sa demmuh kcurt ehT
.sknurt eert mlap fo swodahs eht neewteb seye ym dehcrocs nus eht ,tekciht eht fo egde eht ot dellor ew sA
.sraey evlewT“
.nottub llac eht revo derevoh bmuht yM
.sdaor railimaf otno kcab denrut dna
”.trap ysae eht saw gnitanoD .won boj rieht s’tI
.ssenekil sih derutpac I epoh I“
resolc pu dne ot dnet srentrap
”.retal klat dna ti tuoba mih ksa dluoc I ?rebmun ym tnaw uoY .ylbaborP“
.tsohg a saw ehs thguoht I tsrif tA  terreFekuD yb
.gninrom siht tisnart koot I“
hguorht—yaw yna ni detcennoc eb thgim ohw wonk uoy enoyna rO
,lufepoh tey ,liarf
;krow lacisyhp otni ton m’I
.ytic reggib a dekcip ev’dluoc uoY“  ”?mH“  ”?ereh yhw...oS“
”.kcab tuctrohs a gnikat saw I .eeyolpme na rof revoc ot ehaL ot evorD“  ”?neht
?yas neve I dluoc tahW
.hgual t’ndid anuL  ”?skrap reliart rieht dna sdik ytiC“ .derekcins I
”.emoh ot esolc taht
.nrob saw I erofeb ylluS ot devom eh tub ,ereh nrob saw dad yM .kcab delaid os saw erutcurtsarfni tahT“  ”?tahW“  ”.em
.seilfrettub emos em evag thguoht tahT
”.dnabsuh ruoy ekil htrib morf ti nrael naht rehtar ,tluda na sa ereh tpada ot dah uoY
thgiE“  .enohp a decudorp ehs tekcop reh morF
”.ti gnihcteks ylno m’I yhw s’tahT .wonk I ,hO“
.kcurt a ekil em tih ekoj ehT
.koob reh ot nwod kcab denrut ehs ,resare reh no gniwehc retfA
”.emaf etad ot gniyrt seizarc fo tol a
.tnorf ni wollef roop eht dne-raer ton ot krap ot raeg eht tes ot daH
revo ereh detrats I
.langis nrut eht fo gnikcit eht morf trapa
— floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,terreFekuD yb
.kramer taht derongi ehS
”.reirrac rettel eht yeliR“
”?efilretfa ehT ?tahw tA“
”?sdik evah uoy oD ?uoy tuoba tahW“
”?yeht t’nera ,sniur eht era esohT“
..rekih-hctih flowerew
,teY .seye sih morf ylno ekops ,oot ,rentrap siH
ruf s’anuL no etihw cilegna gniwolg nus eht htiw ytic eht otni su gnittel ,neerg denrut thgil ciffart ehT
.daor eht ot kcab denrut dna daeh ym koohs I
.emitefil a sa gnol sa tlef gnir driht ehT
.deid ehs litnu pU
.taht tegrof em edam
”?ylluS ni gnivil nevE“ .seye citehtapmys htiw em deiduts ehS ”.yrros os m’I .hO“  ”.deid
.rae ym ot enohp eht desserp dna egnulp eht koot I ,htaerb peed a htiW
”?niaga ynoloc tsol ruoy htiw od ot evah siht seod tahW“
”?gnihtyna htiw od ot evah taht seod tahw ,tiaW“
”.meht fo draeh reveN“
”.wonk uoy ,gnizigolopa pots nac uoY“
.elims a dih ylerab taht spil desrup ehS ”.hO“
.strap eseht dnuora draeh etiuq t’ndah I taht ti ot eltsihw a dah eciov reH
.srosiv nus ruo nwod tup eW
.dooh reh yawa dellup ehs nehw egnaro ot yerg ot kcalb gnidnelb ruf trohs
”.etad driht ruo litnu emaf gniworg sih tuoba em llet neve t’ndid eH“
!elbidercni si siht ,anuL“ .ti tuohtiw em ees t’ndluoc ehs sseug I ;ylinnuf
”nwotemoH ruoY nI m’I“
.deppots gnilbbircs reH  ”?seton gnikaT“
.ega taht ecnis efil ym flah devil d’I ekil tlef neve ti taht ton—
ruf reh fo llems eht welb C/A ehT
”.ziuL dna em ,semit wef a ereht tuo dekih eW“  ”?yadot erofeb
,knird ym deppis I
.stnuocca aidem laicos yrruf sih no ylraluger krowtra dna
.nekops t’ndah I fi sa deunitnoc ehS
.pmaws eht fo egnirf eht fo rekram a ,snwot gniredrob sdrawot detniop ngis nedoow A  ”.uoy knahT“
.yawa sdray lareves seert eht fo tuo deppets—
”?senob pu gniggid ,ekiL .hO“  .deifiralc ehs
”.wonk’y ,thgie retfa ereh tuo eb t’ndluohs uoY
.rorrim eht ni seye reh ot
.retsof ti tel I sa gnol sa dnim ym evael t’ndluow thguoht ehT
,eye ym ni remmilg lufepoh a saw erehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ereht neeB“  ”.muesum eht ta ffo uoy pord dluoc I ,siht no gniknab si tcejorp ruoy fI
,ereh uoy era yhW“
.esion taht wonk I“
”?seilppus gnipmac htiW“  ”.enola ereh tuo deklaw I nehT
.evirD edismlaP otno llup ot
,taes ym ni kcab dehcuols I
.liameciov ot em tnes ti erofeb pu gnah ot deraperp I ,gnir htfif eht gniruD
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF no
anuL tuoba gnihtemoS
.srettel ynam os dnuora yrrac uoY“  ”?em tuoba tahW“
.dnabsuh reh htiw eviecnoc t’ndluoc ohw dneirf a rof rehtaf etagorrus a saw I ,lleW“ .daeh ym koohs I
.stnuocca tsom ot gnidroccA“
.tsehc ym ni degnap tliuG
”.smussop er’yeht esuaceb tsuj meht htiw pu tup ot evah t’ndluohs uoy tub
s’erehT“ .licnep reh dnuora nups anuL ”?msinahcem esnefeD“
.niaga em ot denrut anuL ,nwotnwod srewot eht gniraeN  ”.thgiR“
.dnalpmaws tesnus eht otni detixe dna draobhsad eht ffo pac ym debbarg I
,emit no ti gnikam fo gnikaepS“
.yas ot tahw yltcaxe em dlot ti ,nepo gnittiS
.rentrap ym ksa ot evah d’I“
”?yeht t’nod erehW“
”.pihsnoitaler yna ni segnellahc ecaf uoy tuB“
.rekcit eht fo mhtyhr eht gnikcimim
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.thgiR“  ”.emit no ti gnikam tuoba erac
.lla ta esnes hcum ekam t’ndid rewsna tahT
.redluohs ym revo detniop I  ”?erehw oT“
,enildnal dlo eht deretsiger ev’tsum I
.tsirw ym no dednal wap reh litnu tekcop ym hguorht degammur I ”...erutcip a ekat em tel ,etunim a tiaW
”?srepap ecnatpecca ynam woH
”.kool resolc a teg ot gniyrt tsuj m’I .oN“
.gnivom deppots licnep reH
.yadot litnu ti fo draeh reveN“
.thgilnus eht ni gnir gniddew ym dehsalf dna su neewteb wap ym devaw I
.loohcs ni tuoba draeh ylbaborp eh senO
”.ereht fo tuo teg ot tiaw t’nac tsuj sdik emoS
,euneva reteiuq a nO
srekcepdoow ylegral—elpoep fo krow ehT
.teef reh tuo dehcterts ehS
.rosiv nus ym pu deppilf I
?epacsE ssertroF nees reve uoY .rekammlif gib ytterp a s’eH
”.sdneirf ym dna em rof tuo yad
”.yromem a tsuJ .dnimreveN“
.spil reh ta deirp elims A
”.kcart-ffo elttil a toG .sknahT“  .ti nmad doG
.daeh ym koohs tsuj I ,thguoht dnoces nO
.neercs SPG eht ot nwod deppans seye yM  ”.thgir a dessim uoy kniht I“  ”?huh hU“
!etuor s’ekiM no t’nerew yeht yllufepoH !ahA“
”?yas yeht tahw rednow reve uoy t’noD
?gnol siht retfa pu kcip llits d’eh kniht I did yhW
”.ereht dna ereh neewteb tsaoc fo tnenitnoc elohw A“
.pal reh morf gnidrocer llits ,enohp reh ta revo decnalg I
”.ti ekat I ,pu gniworg pmaws eht tuoba tib a etiuq denrael eH“
.ti tuoba thguoht I sa noitcesretni eht fo edis rehto eht no dewols ciffarT
,revo noitseuq taht gnikniht tnemom a tneps ehS
.reh denokceb dna dnuora denrut I
seirots trohs sdaolpu ohw
gniward m’I dnA .tsitra na m’I
.teef reh delffuhs anuL
”.emaf tuoba erac t’nod tsuj I !oot yzarc m’I ,hO“ .deffocs I
”.yad ym fo tuo ruoh rehtona tsuj s’tI
.segairram ni secnereffid thgieh gniyduts etamssalc a evah I“
”.oga sraey neetriht dnabsuh ym htiw ereh devoM .epoN“
.yrd tnew htuom yM
.wollof t’ndid ehS
”?ereh ylimaf tog uoY“