.yad eht fo tser eht rof pu em sekaw rewohs mraw-os-ton a dna deb attuo teg I
,tsael ton tub tsaL
ti gninoitseuq yrt t’nseod eH
.kcatta cinap ro llac ecnerefnoc a fo elddim eht ni s’eh fi llet t’nac I dna em rof pu regnif eno tog s’eH
eno siht dna boj a tuo eb d’I neht tub ,taht mih llet annaw I
.mih fo tuo dna ni yot eht spmup rehto eht elihw nwod dna pu mih gnikorts mhtyhr ydaets a gnipeek eno
.siht od s’teL .yddub ,thgirlA
.tniop a fo htnet a neve egareva sih tfihs ot ton gnitar ym rof tib a etiuq sdutS gniredro eb tsum eH
”,doog yllaer er’uoy ,woW“
,lufituaeb s’tI
,sezigolopa dna selkcuhc eH
.elims gnimrahc ylhsilived a no stog dna senin eht ot desserd s’eh ,eit der gnikirts a dna tius epirtsnip eulb thgindim a ni desserd prahS
.gniog teg dna pu sucof ot deen I os ,flesym gniyojne eb ot em rof ti ni trap on s’erehT
.ytic eht otni peed s’eh dna PASA deredner secivres rof tseuqer a gnikam tneilc rallod hgiH !esruoc fO
.em gnignir si krow dna knird ym hsinif ot em rof emit ni tsuJ
,tsehc sih morf spord tsal eht pu gninaelc m’I sA
.daeh elttil etuc ruoy yrrow t’noD
.teg yeht reggib eht rediw yllaitnatsbus teg dna ylevitcepser gnol sehcni net dna ,thgie ,xis ,evif er’yehT
ni em stel etag eht ,selitsnrut eht ot drac DI ym fo hcuot a htiW
.ffo spord tuoba tsuj waj
.lleh lla sa yhsuc si doohrobhgien sihT
.em otni peed hsup ot eunitnoc nac eh os flesym elgna I tub ,kcid eritne sih ni dloh ot hguone gnol etiuq t’nsi elzzum yM
,lworg evitcudes wol a ni yas dna revo lwarc I
.ti od annog m’I ,muc emos pu kcus ot tsuj skcub ytriht taht tuo ezeeuqs nac I taht wonk I fI
tsuj yltsom eh ,wolgretfa sih ni gnihtab llitS
steehs nitas ehT
.ti ta seson rieht nwod gnikool
eliforp sih ni eno eht ekil tsuj
.esroH eht nedyaH dna
.kcab eht ni bac a sdrawot tops a ot yrruh I dna
,mednat ni krow swap ym htoB
,tfahs sih fo sniev eht nwod gninnur yltrepxe eugnot ym htiW .krow ot teg I os
.gniog erp emos teg nac I litnu sbrab fo sehcni enin sih gnola nwod dna pu ekorts I ,tfahs sih dnuora depparw waP
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna eseht piks nac uoy
.em ksa ot esle gnihtemos tog s’eh
.daetsni taht gniod eb dluow I ,ereh tuo devom I nehw krowrepap ym pu xim t’ndid tcirtsid nmad eht fi dna sdik eht htiw taerg m’I
.noitnetta gniyap etiuq ton s’eh tub ,pu elddup spord wef A
.moordeb sih ot llah eht nwod em sdael eh sa daeh ym revo trihs ym llup I .pmahc ,ti tog uoY !taht ta kooL ?esael-huP
.steehs fo tes hserf a evah dna ,demoorg
.deticxe teg dna ma I iDiF eht ni erehw yltcaxe rebmemer I
.htuom ym otni kcab daeh sih gard I sa edisni gnihtyreve gnipeek ,ylthgit mih dnuora parw spil yM
.tuo yaw ym no tsinoitpecer eht ot sgniht ecin emos yas dna tuo enohp ym llup I ,eciffo eht fo tuo gniklaW
.yb gnissap sgnidliub eht no etaxif I dna ,sthgieh eht ot bmilc wols sti seraperp sub ehT
.no gnileenk m’I hcneb eht otno gnoht dna strohs ym dlof I nehw tey drah neve ton m’I
.dnuor erom eno rof xof eht otni evid dna
.elims suovren tub eltneg a htiw
ym gniod tsuj m’I .traehteews ,em ta dam teg t’noD
.esle enoyreve ekil sbulc eht ta eerf rof ti teg dna tuo oG
.ot gnicnalg edis speek eh taht eno eht ees I tub
sseug I os ,yad ym fo tser thgirb a em sehsiw ehS
,hcum oot rof gniksa t’nia eH
?eiggib oN ;evif ,ruoF
,esaelp yas did eh dna
.talps elbidua na htiw nihc ym fo mottob eht tsniaga pu spals tons
pord sredluohs yM .gniD—
,denaelc eb retteb uoy ,em htiw laed
.eb ot tnaem t’nsaw ti sseuG .ymmut yrroS
.no tog s’eh tius ytterp taht niur annaw t’noD
.eugael ym fo tuo yaw dna evisnepxe tub
.enohp ym ta kool I dna
.spu-kooh fo krowsseug eht fo yna tuohtiw tnaw uoy tahw yltcaxe teg ton yhw os
.doom sih llik ot ydaer steg em fo trap dna htuom sih snepo neve eh erofeb ecaf sih no ti ees nac I
ffo yad ym t’nia ti tub ,gnirebmuls yad lla dneps nac em ekil mussopo nA .eb ot tnaem t’nsaw ti sseuG
.pam a dna ,cip eliforp a ,detseuqer secivres ffo og ot teg tsuj I tub
eht htiw gniyalp ,sllab sih eldnof swap yM
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.mih ni gib gnihtemos sdeen yob siht dna sehcni ruof naht regral hcum pu emoc t’nod I
.saelf naht rehto gnihtyna pu gnikcip tuoba yrrow ot evah t’nod I os ,stohs ym lla tog ev’I
.pu sgnah eh litnu seye ylgoog mih evig dna
.ruf tsehc emos em wohs ot erom wef a ffo gnillup dna trihs sih fo nottub pot eht nepo deppop s’eh ,daetsnI
.mih ekil I ykcul s’eH  ”?ton yhW .eruS“
,spu rehgih eht fo emos ot etuc dnuos thgim tahT
.yad lla dnuora spmuhc gnivird og ot rac a evah t’ndid dna hsac kciuq emos dedeen I taht saw boj siht otni tog I yhw nosaer ylno ehT
1 traP ,etoyoCtriD yb
.won semit ruof tub ,eciwt ton ,ecno ton nettog ev’I ,ylgnissarrabme ,hcihW
ylrae denoitnem I sodnoc esoht no sexaT
.egde s’deb eht ot yaw eht lla mih gnirb I sa gnippiy dna ylthgils gnimriuqs ,steehs nitas sih ssorca ylsseltroffe sedils eH
.ekil d’uoy revenehw meht redro nac uoy dna setar ym tog I
.tug ym otni thgiarts tuo hsalps muc leef I dna riahc sih otni tsif a smals eh ,gninraw rof snaom sih ylnO
!em devol sbuc eht dna ,boj ym ta doog nmad saw I !lap ,uoy kcuf ,thguoht dnoces ,yllautcA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.niaga ppa sih ni pu wohs reven ll’I taht seetnaraug tsuj srats eerht eht esuac ,hguoht thgirla s’tahT
ynam os gnikat eb t’ndluohs I dna syawyna ssenisub retteb s’ytiC .ti kcuf ,hhA
.cinahcem a ot sloot gnidnah tnatsissa na ekil em ot revo ynnaF sgnirb liat yM
.slirtson ym attuo toohs nac ti
dna tnecs sih fo lla gnilahni m’I ,flesym gnitnaP
.yug gib a s’eH .kceh ,wA
.diap gnitteg m’I yhw s’tahT .ko s’tahT
dna tuo em sevaw
.steehs ym ni rethgit pu depparw gnitteg ,elttil a rits I
.melborp on ;regnif enO
.pu kcuf eht sgniht deeps ot mih egaruocne ot ekilyxes lla sehtolc emos ffo gnippirts trats dluohs I ebyaM
.flesmih fo erac doog nmad gnikat tsuj si ro seitrof ylrae sih ni eb ot skool eH
plug I tub ,eugnot ym tsniaga muc trups ot seunitnoc tI
.ni yawflah s’ti emit eht yb naom peed gnol a otni sehcterts dna mih morf psag ynit yneet a steg tahT
.tuo semoc ti naht retsaf nwod ti
”.llac txen ym erofeb tsaf pu siht parw attoG .nO“
.mih reffo ot tol elohw a evah I taht ton ,egakcap ym ni detseretni hcum os
.htiw tneulf m’I ylno egaugnal dnoces a ekil senihw dna stnap sih gnidaer ,mih revo mool I
.ni tes wolgretfa eht stel dna
em sa 4’5 emas tcaxe eht sdnats eh ,yltnasaelp detnecs dna demoorG
.pu kcab thguorb I
,pu denaelc su teg ot nigeb nac I erofeb tub
,srexob klis ssarb emos no tog s’yuG
elzzum sih fo edis eht tuo gnilgnad s’eugnot siH
t’nia eH .ekam ot snoisiced emos tog uoY
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.htiw ni deklaw I 9.4 eht ta gnittis llits s’eh ,dloheb dna ol ,dna ,erocs sih kcehc I ytisoiruc fo tuO .niaga reveN
.ees ot enipluv eht rof liat ym ni nogarD lacitsatnaF eht ynnaF pu gnidloh m’I
.riahc ni flesmih stsujda eh elihw taesevol rehtael a otno nwod gab ym tis I
,elzzum ym edisni sborht tI
.htaehs sih fo tuo erom gnixaoc dna pit knip sih gnikorts ,tfahs gnigreme sih fo dloh barg I ,wap eno htiW
,kcab seog daeh siH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ytic eht ni yad sih sehsinif dutS ehT woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni
gnirebmemer erofeb ,flesym tneiro ot elcric a ni dnuora nips dna tseuqer eht tpecca I
,nwod selttes yllanif eh nehW
”?esaelp ,ydob ym no muc eht pu kcil ot uoy deksa I fi thgirla eb ti dluoW“
ym dna kconk I sa noos sa tsomla srewsna eH
.ees t’ndid srobhgien eht erus ekam ot fi sa edistuo keep kciuq a gnikat ,yllufhsab edisni em setivni dna
eizzom I ,redluohs ym revo gnuls seidoog fo kcapkcab ym htiW
.dnoces a rof revo ti kniht dna secivres detseuqer eht daer I
,thgirlA .ytreporp ynapmoc gnigamad og annaw t’noD
ppa eht no nrut uoy nehw ees uoy syug tsrif eht fo eno m’I ,gnitar ylhtnom egareva 59.4 a deniatniam ev’I taht woN
eht erehw ssem gnikool ykcat a ,ogol dutS eht sehsalf neercs eht ,sdaol ti elihW
.deerga ydaerla s’eh ,ni sgnirrae fo tes wobniar a gnipool hsinif I erofeb dna em nevig s’eh tols eht nihtiw llew s’tI
.pu ti kcil dna ni nael tsuj ot ’nihton em tsoc t’nseod tI
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
.leef thgim ti thguoht I sa dab retrauq a gnileef t’nsi waj ym dna ,yad ym ffo kcik ot yaw dab a toN
,hguoht semitemos sekyt eht ssim adnik I
,hsP .meht otni gnidderhs swalc prahs sih rof hctam on era
.nwod yaw eht lla meht gut I sa
.ni 52:01 eht hctac ot emit ni tsuj lanimret eht ta evirra I dna gnidliub ym morf klaw trohs a si liar deeps hgih eht nwod gnitteG
.eiskool a teg s’teL .yaw ym ni adnik tsuj ,yltsenoh dna
ruf yna llup ot ton luferac
.eurt ton s’taht ,lleW —emit eerf rieht ni od ot stnaw enoyna tahw htiw smelborp yna evah I taht ton s’tI .sreretludA
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.knab eht ni yenoM
”?esaelp ,ffo sruoy gnikat dnim uoy dluoW“
.egaenil rieht tuohguorht nwod sesuoh eseht gnissap seilimaf yenom dlo fo tol a era eseht tcepsus I
.deb eht no tuo flesmih slwarps eh elihw no kcapkcab dna sehtolc ym tis ot em rof deb eht fo dne eht no hcneb a s’erehT
.worbeye dehcra eht dna spil sih pu gnivruc elims ytsul eht tuo ekam I litnu dnoces a rof ylno sgnah cigam ehT
litnu retaw htuom ym gnikam ydaerla si sdnomla dna alonarg htiw ananab yrrebwartS
.elims a si leehw eht dniheb drehpehS namreG eht evig I lla os ,riaf ym yap
.deracs os eb t’nod ,wA
.daeh sih fo kcab eht otni pu dellor era seye sih dna
tpecca kcilc I
.tsael ta ,eniM .si ti no sehtolC
deb sih otni kcab snael eh sa
.em gnidnuorrus sgnidliub leets dna ssalg eht gnivresbo
”.kcuuuuuuffffF“ .no gniog s’tahw swonk rood taht fo edis rehto eht no enoyreve dnim ym ni tbuod on s’ereht dna eciffo eht otni tuo epacse srepmihw dna snaoM
.teef ym ot teg I sa srettum eh
sees remotsuc eht lla
.nwod em mals dna em barg ot stnaw yllaer eH
.eciffo renroc sih otni pets I sa em rof nepo rood eht sdloh ehs tsael tA
,tseuqer sih gnitpecca retfA
em steerg eh ,pu delgnat sregniF
stfil tsehc sih sa
.doog ytterp gnileef m’I dna pu gnitrats yllaer si yad ym woN
.ssalg eht ot desserp tsomla elzzum ym
.kcoc sih nwod em ediug spleh dna daeh ym fo kcab eht ot wap a stup eH
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
,niaga teerts eht otni tuo gnippetS
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht eht saw sihT
,naelc mih gnikciL
,eborhtab sih ffo gnillup fo daetsnI
.lworp eht no sevlow deye yrgnuh
.ti rof krow ot em gnitcepxe s’eh sseug I os ,hctorc sih ot evom a gnikam t’nia eH
.tsom ta os ro keew a ecno raeh ylno ylbaborp I hcihw
.neht dloc oot steg ti esuac thgin ta no ti evael t’nod I dna naf gniliec yknid ym si tog I lla ,haN .ni gniyats m’I stnemtrapa lanummoc eht ni dradnats emoc yltcaxe t’nod taht tub ,esuoh eht ni CA emos morf tifeneb em ekil sresir etaL
,mih htiw sgnilaed rieht od nac yob rehto emoS
.taht noitnem ylbaborp dluohs I ,thgiR
,oh oh hO .flesmih gnixaler
.em rof tfel s’eh tahw pu pal I nehw
gniog em gnitteg adnik s’eh dna srotaderp gib eht rof ecnereferp a tog ev’I tub ,eil annog toN
.gnorw tnew gnihton tub ,gnorw tnew tahw gniksa eb thgim uoy ,woN
.sregnif ym revo lla ti triuqs dna tuo ebul gnirb I elihw ylgnitnuat dnuora gnivaw ,ria eht ni gnibbob odlid eht si em dniheB
.dnatsthgin eht no enohp sih rof gnivid s’eh
.tsehc sih ni gnidih 8v a tog s’eh ekil gnirrup s’eh esuac‘ ,kool yeht naht rekciht era srood sih yllufepoH !taht sekil eH .ylideerg pu pal I taht slraep wen lareves em snrae tahT .pit der sih revo ssik gnol a mih gnivig dna drawrof gnihcaer erofeb pu mih nekcils I
.riaf eht etsaw annaw I sselnu ylrae kcab gnimoc on t’nia ereht ,ereht tuo m’I ecno snaem hcihw niart eht ekat ot evah annog m’I .yadirF a s’ti dna ytic eht fo elddim eht ni s’eh tub
.htiw nigeb ot gniht ym yllaer t’nsaw ma5 ta pu gnikaw tub
.ytic renni eht hguorht evom ew sa sexelpmoc rof kaerb sreparcsykS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
erofeb doow eht tsniaga nwod gnihtemos gnippals ,ksed sih ot wap rehto sih hcaer mih eciton I
.seye latsyrc lufituaeb eseht htiw em ta nwod gnirats s’eh
?I t’nod ,od ot boj a tog I sseug I ,thgir hO
.won taht tuoba kniht t’naC .starb ysion nezod a yb deluam gnitteg mussopo ssa ykrod ot reltsuh redro elam yxes morf og I dna ,sgnirrae eht evomer ,sessalg eht ddA .eit
.htgnel sih dnuora selcric ni eugnot ym nur dna tfahs sih dnuora spil ym parw I erofeb kcab flesym dloh ylerab nac I
,tcere ylluf saw I fi nevE
.tuo llif ot em rof ydaer srats ytpme evif s’ereht ,sdaol ti nehw dna ppa dutS ym pu gnirb I .reh rof ,lleW
.pu gniwohs rof emarf emit ym mih evig dna
,htrof dna kcab meht revo gnissolg
,eciohc a ekam ot tnatiseh smees eH
.emosdnah ,ereht yeH
.htaehs derruf etihw sih fo tuo gnikop kcoc sih fo pit knip eht
.eugnot ym no yltaen gnicnalab kcoc sih ees nac eh os ediw wam ym nepo I
,lle h lla sa yduag er’yehT
.moor ym gnikooc dna ni gnipeerc neeb s’nus eht tub ,peels ot kcab og ot ydaer m’I
.ylf sih gnippiznu erofeb esool ti ymmihs dna nottub stnap sih fo dloh barg I ,seenk ym no nwoD
,69.4 revo ti peek I sa gnol os dna won thgir 79.4 ta gnittis m’I ,yllautcA .ytilautcnup si taht fo trap dna egareva 59.4 ,dias I ekiL .tnemtnioppa na rof etal neeb ecno reve t’nia I dna em rof gnitiaw s’regit ym ,oslA .gnola gnivom ffo retteb I os ,htnom a 000,01$
.mih no gnitiaw ystna gnitteg m’I dna siht fo etunim a
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.nottub dnes eht kcilc dna eerht mih evig I
.moor eht pu sthgil yllaretil tsomla
etuc neeb sah xof siht tuB
.stiaw eh elihw flesmih gnikorts ,munrets ot wap a sehcuot eh dna tuo separd ruf etihW
.elkna sih fo dloh barg dna deb eht ssorca wap eno hcaer I
.yad eht rof sgniteem sih htiw kcul fo tseb mih hsiw dna
.sgnileef drah on
.elohliat sih tsniaga daeh nailitper detniop eht gninil erofeb
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
.emit erom eno em redro nac eh os srats evif mih evig dna
,hcum t’nsi tneR .syad flah
.eldnah t’nac I gnihton s’ti tub
?knuhtadohW
,taorht ym ni stif ylerab tsuj daeh taf siH
.oga dnoces a nevig saw I ssenetilop emas taht fo yna tuohtiw wollof ot em rof srettum ehS
.O tniop evif tcefrep a si
.gnidliub thgir eht dnif I litnu teerts eht nwod no
,em ksa uoy fi esnes ekam t’nseod tI
!yug hguot ,ereht swalc eht htiw luferaC
.nwod nur adnik dna sselluos er’yeht tub ,tegdub ym nihtiw eb thgim stnemtrapa esohT
.edis eht no gnihtemos gnihtemos elttil a ni worht ot syap tI !eeS
.dlrow ’ninrom doog ,hhA  2 fo
.pot no gnittis ppa dutS eht rof noitacifiton eht no kcilc dna enohp ym tuo llup I
,thgir sleef siht tuoba gnihtemoS
.enog si elims eht dnA
.boj ym ta doog m’I dna yad eht fo dne eht ta lanoisseforp a m’I
.moorssalc eht ot kcab og dluoc I sseug I
tnemilpmoc eht tpecca I
.taht naht tsedom erom m’I ,yakO .wonk I
enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
.ssa s’tar a evig ot mees t’nseod eh
.txen gnimoc s’tahw fo noitapicitna deticxe ni sllaf dna
.yadot eit on tub ,erutcip
tnemilpmoc eht rof mih knaht I
debul dna ecin ti teg I ,htgnel eht nwod dna pu swap ym gnibbuR .ereh dneirf etuc ym rof melborp a eb ot gniog ton yletinifed tub ,swap ym ni yvaeh s’tI .esrun ,uoy knahT
.srats ees seye ym gnikam s’ti
?eerf emoc ot slian eht detcepxe tsuj dna erots erawdrah a ni remmah a deredro uoy evah semit ynam woH
.citsatnaf saw taht ,haoW“
.tsiseiceps on t’nia I .shateehc ton ,oN
.mih revo gnilwarc m’I elihw ydob sih fo ssenesolc eht dna
.sub tseraen eht otno poh attog I ,ti ekam annaw I fI
riahc sih ni gnihcuols erofeb ylffits em ot sezigolopa eh
.keew lluf a ni meht dah t’nevah I dna
.ahc’truh annog t’nia I
.gninepo evitisnes sih ta regnif dna nwod hcaer I sa yltfos srumrum dna seye sih sesolc eH
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.evirra ot em rof emit ni tsuj rood eht snepo revird ehT
.yltnatsni ti steg eh dna taorht ym raelc I ,pu gnikooL
.sretaehc htiw krow t’nod I
.sserts yadkrow emos eldnah ot
.msagro sih tuo edir ot eunitnoc I elihw gnici ni flesmih tsorf xof siht tel I ,sdrawpu mih gnilgnA
.doog ytterp llits ;sregnif eerht ,owT
floW eht ylliW si wap tfel ym nI
.neht dna won yreve meht fo erac ekat ot nam gib a ekil flesym sa hcus smussopo elttiL ?yas I nac tahW .oot
,hguoht ,ni m’I enummoc ynit eht teg ot hguone ykcul saw I
.nwot fo sehctertstuo eht gnola sletom yttihs ot em koot sboj dna gnitrats tsuj saw I nehw kcab saw taht tuB
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,allevon a
.xof eht ffuts I sa esolc mih peek ot elkna sih dnuora gnipparw
.ffo mih gnitteg no sucof tsuj nac I
,sekorts eht htiw retsaf tib ysneet a tsuJ
”.51:11 s’yeldraY .rM m’I ,seY .olleH“
ksed eht otni nael I os
ruf ym ni retaw dloc eht tesffo eeffoc toh dna noitasrevnoc thgiL
,elzzum sih no kcohs fo noisserpxe eht morF
.skeehc eht ta dehsulf gnileef ,kcab elims I
.elims ytsul siht em sevig dna no tog I sgnirrae fo tes wobniar eht sehctac eH !al al ooO
.eno yb eno srepleh fo maet ynit-os-ton ym tuo llup I
.gnihtemos ro liat desiar a eb ot esops‘ si S
.ruf sih ni muc fo sloop eht pu gnippal nigeb dna nwod hcaer I ,revo gninaeL
.egde sti no pmur ym tser dna ksed eht dnuora klaw I sa yltneitap em rof gnitiaw tsuj s’eH
.gnitsat tnasaelp esiwrehto tub ,ytlas dat a s’eH
,ti rof yap ot yenom eht tog s’eh dna ysae si sihT
:rewsna detacilpmoC
.allef ’lil er’emoC
.htgnel sih nwod dna pu elzzum ym edilg I
,dnabtsiaw sih otni swap htob parw dna pu hcaer I
.sdutS sa sevlesruo ot refer ot su fo lla ksa yeht
.elzzum ym no debbals tfel s’eh zzij eht tuoba gnikramer nwo ym fo eno mih evig dna
,ekil era sodnoc ,ylsuoireS
,niks evitisnes sih otni erp sih gnikroW
”?ffo sehtolc ro no sehtolC“
,kcolc eht no m’I tub ,allef yrroS
.dnert a detrats ev’I ?taht raeh uoY
,hguoht eciffo sih evael I sA
.htlaeh ym rof dab osla s’tI
eson ym tsniaga gnihcuot ruf tfos eht fo leef eht si trap tseb ehT
.mih rof pu meht llup dna
”,doog yllaer er’uoY
.regiT eht ymmiT s’ereht ,wap thgir ym nI
.evivrus ll’eh tub ,tsaf oot elttil A
,sehtolc eht ekil tub
.sppa eseht htiw melborp eht s’tahT
.tsermra eht no ti selttes dna rehtegotla wap sih sevomer eh esuac melborp raluger a eb tsuM
,noitats eht fo tuo gnimoc dnoces a rof ni ytic eht ekat I
.ma I ohw wonk ot kcapkcab ym no ogol dutS eht ees ot deen neve t’nseod ehS
.seinohc ym tub gnihton ni wodniw a tuo evid yllacitcarp ot evah I dna em ta gnigniws dna gnimaercs stratS .moor eht ni gnigrab semoc dneirfyob tibbar evif toof xis sih nehw flow ykniwt siht ta yawa gnidnuop saw I emit eno saw erehT
moor eht llif srepmihW
.od ot elpoep tog ev’I dna
,kciuq mih otni sehcni eerht rehtona hsup I
erofeb nac I sa hcum sa pu knird ot decrof ,kcaba nekat m’I
,flesym ecudortni dna evaw I
.si ynapmoc sih tsael ta ro ,dedaol s’yuG
,lleW .si ti erehT
er’yeht ekil ytic eht fo tser eht revo dnats semoh yrots owt dekcap ylthgit etihW
,pu sthgil neercs eht dna hsalf A .saelf eht dloH
,ni snioj liat yM
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.yltaen teprac der hsulp eht stnecca
?sseug I ,leef eht sekil tsuj eh ebyam ro ,tahT .tniop emos ta meht otni dedart ro
,kcapkcab ym otni gnihcaeR
.hgis a ekil tuo stel eh
”,taht tuoba yrroS“
!pu tnep saw yllaer eh ,parc yloH
.sexof eseht fo emos no sesicrexe gnihcterts eht ,zeeJ
.mih morf laeuqs dehctip hgih a gnitteg
.eituc ,elbatrofmoc oot teg t’nod ,yeH
.pord tsal yreve fo sllab sih niard ot pit sih no elkcus I
,oslA .yenom ysae si
.nwod dekohc ev’I kcoc tseggib eht ton ylniatrec s’ti dna siht rof deniart ev’I tub ,waj eros a htiw ffo yad ym trats ton rehtar d’I
,levon a gnitirw si
.gniht siht mia I erehw luferac eb dluohs I sseug ,spoohW
,ereht ni sezeeuqs tonk emos dda
tius a gniraew s’regit ehT
.trocse na ro reltsuh a dellac gnieb dnim t’nod I tub
,noitisop otni kcab teg neve nac I erofeb dna ylleb ym tsniaga gnibbur si ssenffits siH .niaga olleh ,hO
yad sih fo trats eht morf siht dennalp rehtie yletinifed eh os
,hguoht ,rekrow xes a m’I .ti teg eW
wob dna trihs derekcehc eulb ym ni em ees dluohs uoy dna
”.ffo egde eht ekat ot gnihtemos deen yllaer tsuj I dna yad lla sgniteeM“ .detsuahxe
.thgiR .ksed sih no revo dekconk emarf erutcip eht eciton I
.ecneirepxe krow roirp ym rof yltsom noitacilppa ym detpecca yeht kniht I
.tellug ym ni erp erom tisoped ot pu gniralf
.emit rehto yna knird taht em yub nac uoy tub
.em raen pots sub a
hcneb eht ffo stnap ym llup I sa elkcuhc I
mih dniheb aznederc gnihctam dna ksed doowyrrehc krad ehT
.smoor kcab eht ni no gniog saw tahw fo ffihw a tog RH litnu pu boj ym dah ylbaborp ehS
.ssenisub ym fo enon t’nia taht dna
tonk siH !MALB ,ylneddus dna liat ym fo pit eht htiw selos sih elkcit ,rewols tib a mih ni gard yot eht tel
.no eborhtab a tub gnihton htiw yawrood eht ni gnidnats si xof citcra etihw wons sihT
,mih ni yltsom odlid eht htiW
.ysuolaej fo tib a esnes nac I ,pu em gnizis s’ehs taht yaw eht yB .boj
.eruces atros dna ,larutan
.flesym os yas I fi ,yad ym ot trats dab a ton ,yeH
.ydaets mhtyhr ym dna hteet ym morf raelc ti peek I tub
.yddub ,gniod er’uoy tahw wonk t’nod I kniht t’nod
.pit a fo noitnem emos sekam
dna sllub gniltsub gib yb dednuorrus er’ew nehw semitemos suovren teg su ekil syug trohS .ti teg I
.regit elam a fo erutcip a htiw gnola pam a pu gniworht
.emoh kcab yaw sih skrow dna
,sraey owt tsap eseht tniop yna ta deilppaer ev’dluoC
.tsaf os muc ot mih tog I desirprus s’eh neve
,nepo flah era seye s’regit ehT
.taht ekil steehs htiw tfos siht deb a no gnipeels eb ot tun thgir ym eviG .sdik hcir
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.yrotsih si tser eht dna ,stnelat derevocsidnu emos dnuof ,dutS htiw pu dengiS
.esuoh stneilc eht morf yawa kcolb a tuoba tuo pmuj I
.pord elgnis a ssim t’ndiD
,pu syella elpuoc a tsuj tops oyorf rellik a s’erehT
ereh ni pu klaw em gnittel eye dnilb a snrut tub ,tsinoitpecer eht gnikcuf tnemeganam htiw melborp attog s’ycilop tluaf ym t’niA
uoy nehW .erom on secalp ydees eht ni spu-kooh yna ekat t’nod I dna
,redro rieht ecalp yeht erofeb em tuoba liated elgnis yreve wonk ot teg sremotsuC
.artxe ay tsoc d’tahT
,hguoht gniog peek I erofeB
.sniatruc on s’ereht tub ,edistuo gnicaf swodniw eht ot ecnalg I
.og ot ydaer m’I dna
.nehctik derahs eht ni edistuo pets I dna trihs-t etihw a barg I ,gnoht knip ym revo snaej thgit fo riap a no gnippilS
ot semoc ylwols eh erofeb ecaps otni ffo gnirats
.oN :rewsna elpmis eht
,ssenisub ym ediseb s’taht tuB
edis eht ot enohp ym ssot I
.strap teiuq eseht naht ylevil erom secalp ot kcits sklof rotsevni dna ,rehcraeser ,hcet eht fo tsoM
.drac ynapmoc eht no ylbaborp m’I ,kceH
:taht ylno ton tub ,ti fo naf gib a ton m’I dna ymmucs elttil a s’tI
?wonk uoy od tahW .gniD
.rof gnikool s’eh tahw swonk yllaer eno siht ,sediseB
,pu gnipparw si llac sih taht llet nac I
srexob sih otni kcab tfahs sih pleh I
.lluks ym otni spit esoht gniggid yllaer s’eh tub ,taht ekil ekoj t’ndluohs I
taht elims eniuqe yhtoot lufituaeb a tog s’ohw eram a yb deteerg m’I ,aera noitpecer eht otni llorts I sA
.sregnif ym neewteb sbro etihw yvaeh
.taorht ym fo kcab eht otni thgir stlih ti litnu tfahs sih fo lla ni gnikat ,flesym nwod og I esuac ,ot evah t’now eh gniht dooG
,wodniw eht tuo kool nac I erehw tops a kcip I
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“   :yojne esaelP
,krow ym etaicerppa ot elpoep rof ecneidua na gnivah yojne elpoep emoS
,kcapkcab eht otni swap ym ni sodlid eht fo eerht gnissoT .dik ,derevoc ahctoG
.rof tiderc mih sevig cip eliforp sih naht suoegrog erom hcum os s’eH
.steehs der nitas eht revo ydob ekilduolc lufituaeb sih em swohs dna pu ti snepo eh
.siht ekil ppa na gnisu thgir on evah uoy ,nuH
”?ffo sehtolc ro no sehtolC .melborp oN“
tuoB‘ .draobyek eht ta yawa skcalc-kcilc eh elihw eciffo eht fo tser eht ot tuo gnicaf swodniw eht redduhs dna em dniheb rood eht kcol I ,elbatrofmoc teg ot emit ym gnikaT
.rehcaet netragrednik a eb ot desu I ,mhtirogla na yb dnuora deredro gnitteg saw I erofeb ,skcits eht ni kcaB
,fmM .dlrow thgin dooG
.hsac gninrae fo daetsni semag oediv gniyalp eb rehtar d’I esuaceb tsuj sgnivas ym otni gnippid eb annaw t’nod I dna ti ewo llits I tub
.drawrof thgiarts ytterp lla s’ti tub ,nwod klaw ot yawllah hcihw dna no s’eh roolf tahw tuoba ppa eht ni regit eht morf snoitcerid s’erehT
.htaenrednu citsalp eht otni sevruc gniggard swalc sih raeh nac I
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw