.flesym yb ti gniyojne moor ym ni m’I nehw muc ot ekil ylno I .t’nod I ,ylniaM
.niart a no moorhtab a ni t’nerew ew ekil gninaom s’eh
.ysae boj ym sekam tahT
.yadot srallod derdnuh xis revo edam ev’I taht ees osla nac I !eciN
.nepo sgniws rood eht erofeb elbissop sa ylitsah sa pu gninaelc s’eh llet nac I dna
.stohs dna satiragram revo llirG dna raB sorenabaH eht ta pu ti ’nikkay dna ’nikkuy era slag eht lla dna em ,tey retteB
!mih ta hgual t’nod hO
,semutsoc orehrepus ,stuotuc eivom draobdrac ,senirugif noitcA
”?rehto hcae fo tnorf ni ffo krej tsuj ot tnaw uoy dluoW“
edis rehto eht no gnilffuhs emos s’erehT
.tuo ssap tsomla ew erofeb mih egdun I
.moordeb sih ni ti ta gniog yllaer taog siht
?secivres eht s’tahW .yddub ,thgirlA
?elfir taht no stimrep tog uoy ,dik zeeJ
.yddub ,gniht eruS“
,laed gib a hcus t’nsi taht ,yakO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,won em ta gnikool s’eh
.derit adnik gnileef m’I won thgir tub ,ebyaM
,llits dna ,teg nac uoy taht sdutS detar pot tsom eht fo eno m’I ,wonk uoY
,llebrood eht gnir ,edistuo kcab og ,no ti tup I
,semit elpuoc a ebyam nehctik eht ni mih nees ev’I
syawyna em no kciht ydaerla stnecs sih dna
].xof citcra na htiw pu sgniht gnipparw fo elddim eht ni thgir saw dna tneilc tsrif sih dehsinif tsuj dah
”.taht od s’teL .yddub ,haeY“
,hcamots ym ,tsehc ym revo lla s’tI
.teerts eht otno tuo klaw dna yltfos rood eht esolc I os ,flesym gniyojne eb ot em rof ti ni trap on t’niA .yltneg erons mih ot gninetsil tsuj elihw gnivael wols m’I tub
taes sih fo tuo steg eh ,setunim owt tuoba retfA
.tuhs htuom ym peek attog ev’I syas taht selur eht ni gnihton t’nia erehT .esolc neve toN
llems sih dnim yllaer t’nod I
.em morf ssorca thgir emas eht seod eh dna
,tseuqer sih tpecca I
,terces elttil ruO
.gniD railimaf taht raeh I taht gnitar sih mih gnivig morf etunim lluf a neve ton s’tI
.won thgir noitauqe eht otni llaf yllaer t’nseod tnaw I tahw os ,em deredro uoy ;em redro t’ndid I ,tsriF
.ffo flesym gnitaeb elihw thgiew sih tsniaga pu gninael
.yddub ,hu huN ”?deb eht no eldduc ew naC“
.syawyna annaw I tub ,flesym yojne ot em rof siht ni ecalp on t’nia erehT
.pot ’nikaerf eht ta thgir si eno tahT
trihs sih htaenrednu kooh sregnif ym nehw steg eh taht llirht a s’erehT
:yddub ,hsalfsweN
.sgniht eerht ,lleW
,toiR guoD fo tuotuc draobdrac eht tuoba mih htiw klat ot ekil d’I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.em tsurt attog s’eh os ,llet nac eh sa raf sa O tniop evif no gnittis m’I ?tahW
.semitemos neppah sekatsim
.azzip sih rof yap nac eh yaw rehto yna s’ereht fi em sksa eh dna
.staes eht revo lla knups rieht dehsalps dna niart siht no sedud nezod elpuoc a tsael ta ffo dekcahw ev’I
,neht neve dna 03$ stsoc noitadargeD
.knird taht no pu mih ekat thgim I emit txen
,flesym tuo nrow m’I ebyaM .allef etuC
.flesmih ot gnirekcins si tnorf eht ta rotcudnoc eht erus m’I taht hguone duol saw rekcuF .em no seye fo stes s’ereht dna taes ym ot kcab gniklaw m’I
,’nikool doog yas t’ndid eh tuB
,ma I sa tcefrep sa tub ,kcid s’eno on tneb reve t’nia I ,thgirlA
,htaehs ym fo tuo yaw eht lla m’I
.ylurt sruoy fo krow eht fo sniamer ytsurc eht ni gnittis er’uoY .thgir s’tahT
”,nees reve ev’I onihr yna naht reggiB
”.peels emos flesruoy teg
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
,dutS eht[ ,emit tsaL
.gnitar O tniop 5 tcefrep a ta gnittis m’I ees I
.sreksihw ym no hsalps yttib ytti na ,siht s’tahw ,dna
gnidliub ym ot llah eht nwod gniklaw m’I .semit dooG
.mih htiw aet erahs ot sreffo tub ekawa peek ot gnilggurts s’eh ,tuo emoc I nehW
.enohp ym morf gniD railimaf eht draeh I nehw
.niaga ti ta og ot derit oot m’I dna semit derdnuh a tsael ta noitasrevnoc siht dah ydaerla ev’ew esuaceb siht fo yna yas annog ton m’I ,driht dnA
.rotagilla ytsriht yrev yrev a dna
gnihtemos tae ot deen I tub ,yug yrroS
,dna kcab gninael s’eH
.dedulcnoc si ssenisub ruo ,denrecnoc m’I sa raf sa dna
.ydob tfos sih leef nac I os ruf hguor sih hguorht gnisserp
.porc gnidir a htiw der ssa s’oppih a gniknaps edishtron eht no nwod m’I
sih ta leenk ot ecaps hguone dnif ot eganam I tub ,ereh ni depmarc s’tI
.yad lla moor sih ni syats eh esiwrehto tub
”,esoht fo tuo uoy pleh emmeL
gnikniht m’I dna em no nwod og ot stnaw dik taR
erutcip sih ta kool I
emarfrood eht fo tuo spets eH
.sneppah tahw ees ll’ew ,syawynA
,on hO .wonk lla uoY
!ecalp elohw eht nwod nrub tsomla eW
,niks deggur hguot eht hcuot I sa noos sA
dna knis eht ni naelc swap ym hsaw tsuj I ,dehsinif s’eh nehW
,xaw toh ni detaoc redrum ydoolb gnimaercs m’I ,kcab ym no thgir nwod emoc seldnac owt ,draobdaeh eht otni degdol teg snroh sih ,yaw rehtiE
.gnihtemos ro citnamor s’ti ebyam gnikniht ,hguoht draobdaeh eht no seldnac til nezod a tog s’eH
.mih fo tnorf ni flesym hcuot ot nigeb I elihw
.cilbup ni dekrej tog enoemos woh tuoba lla raeh ot evol d’yeht erus m’I
”—aF doog a s’tahT“
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
.pu yaw eht lla eton yreve tih ll’uoy ,gnis ot uoy tnaw I nehW
.stseuqer etaidemmi yna gnikat tuohtiw yad ym tuo eludehcs ot em gniwolla
.tneilc a htiw gnihsinif tuoba selur gib tog ev’I ,woN
.sees eh dutS txen eht ot srewolf gnirb retteb eH
?niaga sbuc eht ees ot moorssalc eht otni kcab teg dna ppa eht nwod tup ot dab os eb t’ndluow ti ebyaM
,ti gnidaer s’eh yaw eht yb ees nac I dna sdne htob no emas eht sdnuos ti ,haey hO
tub tner yap ot hguone dooG
,levon a gnitirw si ,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.em gniwollof meht gniwohs si pam eht esuaceb ,taht tsuj gniod eb tsum yeht ,hguoht esirprus ym oT
!hguorht llorcs ot tnuocca aidem laicos a tog ev’I
,detciderp I ekil tsuj
.mhtyhr ym ot flesmih gnicap dna
.teg nac sgniht sa driew sa t’nsi ysatnaf yreviled yob azzip taht si ’niyas m’I llA
.tnemmoc taht htiw raf oot flesmih dednetxe ev’thgim eh ekil skool ,spoO
.flesym tib elttil a ti gniyojne m’I esuaceb siht gniyojne s’eh wonk I
.mih htiw ni kcab kcut dna
,ppa hcet sselluos live na eb thgim dutS
.ecnis yaw emas eht em ta kool ot elba neeb t’nsah ot hturt tsenoh eht dlot reve ev’I taht enoynA
,emit siht em ffo knups sih fo tsom peek ot deganam I ,yllufknahT
dna yad ym fo dne eht ta si ti ,tuB
.taht em sllet reve taht eno ylno eht s’eh
.rehtegot ni teg s’tel ,haN“
.deredner era secivres ym retfa tuo em gol ot swonk ti taht os nottub ”llac tsal“ eht kcilc neht dna ti tpecca I
revird erahsedir ruoy fi ekil ,drawkwa sleef rewohs s’regnarts a esu ot gniksa tuoba gnihtemoS
.efil eritne ym ni no detser ev’I deb elbatrofmoc tsom eht s’ti
,em fo eerht ro owt shgiew ylbaborp ,tesyvaeh s’eH
.depoop ylhguoroht m’I dna
,naom dna kcab daeh ym worht I
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
.drow a tuohtiw reffo eht gnitpecca ,mra sih tuo sdloh dna
er’uoY“ .ydob dekan ym ni gnikat elihw flesmih gnikorts ydaerla
!deb eht ffo flesmih llup ot gnilggurts s’eh elihw
ppa ym ni rats eno a mih gnivig ydaerla m’I esuac ,ton ro erom detnaw eh fi tihs a evig t’noD
,yad lla neeb s’ti naht regral si elims yM
,tnemtrapa ym gninepo fo daetsnI
,sllaw moorhtab emarf leets eht tsniaga ecnuob snaoM
,em ot kcab ylwols ti ediug dna nihc sih hcuot I
.deb sih pota gnittis dna moor nwo sih otni mih gnidael ,repsihw I
”,nees reve ev’I nosrep lufituaeb tsom eht
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht saw sihT
.dutS ruoy tsuj m’I
yllaicepS‘ .gniod dnim t’nod I srehto dna
.emos nwod elttes ot deen tsuj I ebyam ,yakO
”.tsrif ti esu nac uoY“
.sewo eh tahw fo pot no dedda noitadarged eht rof llib a dna
.ti eldnah nac eh os ,erofeb siht enod t’nevah I ekil ton s’tI
.ynnuf ytterp gnieb pu sdne yllautca ti ,xes dnuora ycerces dna samgits evitagen eht lla fo dir teg uoy nehW
,swap ym dna retto eht no si muc ym fo tsom ,esirprus ym oT
.ti sekil eh woh yltcaxe llet nac I
,fffM“ .yadot suoreneg gnileef m’I sseug I
.degnahcxe drow elgnis a tuohtiw tuo klaw
,nuf fo tol a dah I
.dnuora gniyl tog s’eh tihs eht tsom ezingocer I dna
.ecneitap rof hcum oS
.bojdnah a deredro uoy dna edivorp I secivres fo tsil eht ni ”noisses ffokcaj lautum“ rof ppa eht ni gnihton s’erehT
,daeh sih revo ffo semoc trihs eht nehW
.doog nmad ytterp s’tahT
.ti gnikrej trats I os dna
.em rof flesmih gnikorts
.thgil a ekil tuo s’eh ,moor eht fo tuo neve m’I erofeB
?I od ,klat ot moor fo tol elohw a evah t’nod I sseug I ,lleW
.setupsid yna ni em htiw edis ll’yeht ,net fo tuo semit enin tub
,kceH .ees ll’eh dutS tsrif eht eb ll’I ,ppa sih no snrut eh emit txen ehT .tsil derreferp ym ot mih dda ot bat ’snoitpo erom‘ eht nwod llup dna srats evif rehtona mih gnivig hsinif I
.gniht ylno eht ton s’taht tub
.tuo nrow yletelpmoc dna knups nwo sih fo sdaol ytfeh owt ni derevoc s’eh
.ruasonid elprup niatrec a fo emutsoc a no tup em dah knuks emos erehw emit eno siht saw ereht ,kceH
,ruoh txen eht rof kaerb a gnikat eb annog m’I taht ppa eht llet I
:si rewsna eht dna
.ylralimis em dezalg dah retto eht taht ezilaer neve t’ndid I esuaceb
.daeh sih revo pu ti llup dna
—eh elihw gnos eht gnis ot em deksa nevE
.tneb steg kcid lanoisacco eht dna ,delgnat teg sliat ,deknob teg sdaeH
.eye eht ni em kool ot elbanu ,kcab selbmum retto eht ”,ih-H“ ”.ymmiT ,yeH“
.moorhtab dezis tesolc eht sdrawot mih gniwollof dna pu gnitteg erofeb etunim a ti evig I
,ti dnes I ecnO .evif tuoba
.yug siht no ebul etsaw ot deen oN
trihs nwo ym ffo ekat ot sthgif rehto eht elihw wap eno htiw ylleb sih gnibbur m’I
.em ta kool ot elbanu llits ,yltfos sksa eh
.ytic eht fo dne rehto eht no hcaeb eht gnola tuo flow a si taht retfA
.gnikam m’I ssem eht fo erac tuohtiw xamilc I sa ylthgit seye ym gnisolc
.od I sa netfo sa yrots taht elpoep gnillet eb t’ndluohs ylbaborp I ,wonk uoY !yllautcA
yaw trap ni snael eH
,selur eht tsniaga yllatoT
.timreh a ro yag gnieb rof tuo dekcik gnitteg retfa ni nekat neeb ev’thgim eh kniht I tub
.kcab eht sdrawot sklaw dna
,sksa yllanif eh nehw moordeb sih ni ruf ym gniyrd tuo m’I
,sgniht thgir eht lla gniod m’I
.ksum onihr fo duolc elbapacseni na otni gnixim senomorehp dna htaerb sih yltsom si ria ehT
.dik ,ot seog IBU ruoy erehw wonk t’nod I kniht t’noD
.6.3 a ot nwod 9.3 a morf spord gnitar siH
,deb eht otni kcab pu lwarc eW
.em dnuora smra sih sparw eh nehw
gniht rieht tog s’enoyrevE
.ti tuoba teiuq eb annog t’nera uoy taht llet nac I tub ,kcab eht ni ffo uoy krej nac I ,yddub em ot netsiL
.gninrom eht ni gniht tsrif yrdnual eht ot nwod meht teg ll’ew ,worromoT
.spit ym ta erusaelp sih leef I esuac taht wenk I tub
.segamad eht ta nwod kool nac I litnu elzzum ym rewol I ,nwod gnimoC
,doog si hcihw ,desolc era
,daeh ruoy ni gnirednow ylbaborp er’uoY
dekoob m’I dna tsaf ytterp ni emoc stnemtnioppA
.revetahw ro ,elbakcuf ro ,toh ro ,yxes ro ,evitcartta ro
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
s’erehT .wolgretfa ruo yojne ot skcab ruo otno gnispalloc erofeb emit emas eht ta hgual dna
.htaerb ym hctac ot emit emos deen tsuj I tub
.hcamots ytpme na no taht od annog ton yletinifed m’I dna
.detseuqer s’eh secivres eht mih gnivig si nrecnoc ylno ym
.nwod em esahc emoc ot hpm003 goj nac yeht sselnu detnioppasid yleros eb ot tuoba si gnikconk si reveohW
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
.kcab eht ni rood tsal eht ot llah eht nwod kcab klaw I
.kcab eht ni onihr gib eht tops I litnu
.on mih llet nac I os em ksa attog s’eh tub ,si ti tahw wonk I dna dnim sih no gnihtemos s’erehT
dnoces a rof gnikool ,taes ym ni dnuora nrut neht dna
,ti ssim tsomla I dna ,htuom sih tuo srettum gnihtemoS
.sreksihw ym ffo hciwdnas bulc ym morf oyam eht pu kcil I sa tsuj lluf
”?od yug siht t’ndluow tahw“
,mih htaenrednu morf tuo pils I
.taht htiw krow nac I os ,kciht s’eh tsael tA
,emag A ym gnikool llits m’I erus ekam ot kcehc kciuq A
em llac ot yako ton era taht sdrow fo tsil a s’ereht
.dnuora gniyl knuj sih lla htiw mih dnuora teg ot drah adnik s’ti dna
.ni gnikcut erofeb seye sih sllor dna em seciton ,pu skool eH
knuj s’nosrep rehtona raen erehwyna sedalb rozar esoht tup REVE
.dnoces a rof moorhtab sih ni pu nehserf attog ev’I tub
.mih toob lliw ppa eht dna 5.3 woleb pord ll’eh ,4 a naht ssel gnihtyna steg eh fI
?yeht lliw ,sevlesmeht yalp t’now sloop otni gnippirt samdnarg fo soediv esohT
,kcol eht gnikcehc neve tuohtiW
,sedis sih hguorht gard
.tihs a evig t’nod I tub ,slewot emos nwod dial evah dluohs ylbaborP
.em rof xob draobdrac ytpme na dna mrofinu azzip suolucidir a tog s’eh evirra I nehW
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.edud eht no epiws ot evah I dna tsetorp ni elbmurg elttil a em sevig ymmut ym ,ppa eht kcehc I nehW
dehcneuq ylhguoroht si tsriht siH
!yad doog a eb ot gniog si yadoT
detareggaxe t’nsi taht llet I yrots enO
,yltnatiseh srewsna eh tub ,peelsa nellaf s’eh yrrow I ”.rewohs
.meht gnitsiwt dna ylthgit selppin sih gnihcnip trihs sih htaenrednu fooh a tog s’eH .srae ym neewteb niarb ym gnilttar dna ylduol gniohce
swalc ym fo spit ehT
.moortser ruoy esu ot sksa
?ffo worromot ekat ot hguone doog ebyam
.ppa eht ni erehwyna ”srallod neetfif - rehtegot peelsa llaf dna eldduC“ dellac ecivres on t’nia erehT
.kcapkcab ym was eH .thgir ,hO ?kceh eht woH
.kcoc sih fo pmup hcae htiw nwod kcab sllup dna
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,allevon a
stnap ym morf enohp ym tuo llup tsuj daetsni dna ,hguoht t’nod I
sacilper eivom ysatnaf dna
.yltcerroc mih raeh I kniht I tub
.emit eritne eht dnuorg eht ot elzzum sih
2 fo 2 traP ,etoyoC triD yb
.yppah os ton s’eh
!dik pu hctac nac uoy epoH .ylkciuq htrof gnihsur msagro ym leef I
.siht od ot em yap elpoep yhw rednow gnikcuf on s’tI
.won wohs eht hctaw ot gniog er’uoy os ,em rof diap uoY .yug ,hu huN
:ti teg I ,haey haeY
.yad yreve rellat tib eew a steg elat taht ,thgirlA
daeh sih revo sdlof nikserof siH
,tnemom siht tA
,stnalpsnart era stnanet rehto eht fo tsoM
.krow ot gnitteg erofeb doog dna ecin pu meht kcils dna swap ym otni thgir tips I
.weiv raelc a teg nac eh os tfahs ym gnola regnif a gniggard
.’nikool doog m’I taht tnetxe emos ot wonk I
.tuo ekohc ot seganam ylerab tsuj eh
.fo dloh a teg ot tol elohw a t’nia ereht
ni moorhtab eht ni em teem ot ppa eht ni egassem a mih dnes I dna
seye siH .wap ym otni muc gnippird hsinif ot mih rof sdnoces evif txen eht rof looc peek si od attog ev’I llA
.edis ot edis gnihcuot er’ew os flesym noitisop I
,pag eht fo tser eht llif I dna
dna em tuoba si llet ot yrots etirovaf yM
!aH ?em dna uoy neewteb tsuj saw siht thguoht uoY ?taht s’tahW !hO
,yltfos yas I dna
mih htiw siht od ot tnaw I wonk I ,yaw rehtiE
—yaw on t’nia ereht dna taht s’tahT
tsuj m’I ,sekorts fo daetsni tub
,ppa ym nepo gnippilF
.retupmoc ym ot kcab teg dna emoh og ot em rof emit s’ti tub
,hguoht ti tuoba gnikniht neve tuohtiW
.tfig yadhtrib eht gnitteg eno eht s’ohw
.dlrow thgin doog ,hhhhA
]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[    .setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.liatkcoc citamora na otni sexim
,hguoht sgniht ym gnikcaP
.yddub gniht eruS
.wonk ot tnaw t’nod uoy
”.tif nac ew wonk I
seenk ym no elbatrofmoc teg I ,deb eht otno pu gnilwarC
,eh si os dna drah m’I .tius swollof eh dna ffo sehtolc ym fo tser eht pir I sa
?traeh ,em ot siht gniod uoy yhw ,hhhO
.htneethgie s’dneirf rieht rof tfig a sa em ’thguob‘ enoemos emit eht si
.doow eht tsniaga ylthgil pat I dna
.ylleb nworb gib retto eht no enil a taoc ot hguone drah stoohs muc ym fo evaw tsrif eht erofeb elzzum ym tuo skaeuqs yrc delffum A
.rewohs ot deen annog er’eW“
.steehs delios eht htaenrednu gnitteg
.gniD .noitcaer sih hctac ot mih ot kcab nrut I
,won thgir gnileef m’I sa doog sa flah leef stneilc ym ekam nac I fI
.tniop yna ta taht dellac gnitteg rof pu gningis rebmemer t’nod I dna bojdnah a tsuj saw sihT .ssakcaj a tahW
?J ydnaH a tsuJ
roolf eht ot nwod sfeirb dna stnap ,teliot eht no s’eh ,edisni m’I nehW
.dnuora gnikcits rof sknaht ,emitnaem eht nI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.kcirp ynit ,ffo flesruoy gnikrej yojnE
,thgin a saw thginoT
semag emos yalp ot deticxe
,hguorht em stel dna
.ti ot eerga od I fi neve
,llew sa em otni gnildduh s’eH
.ylthgit esrup spil ym dna drow eht hctac I sa tsuj kcab dlof srae yM
.atsim ,em htiw evol ni ’nillaf og t’noD
?ew erew erehw ,thgirlA
.mih tuob‘ yrrow t’noD
sekorts ym gnihctaw
,nruter on fo tniop eht tsap hcaer mih leef I sA
.no kcab gniht nmad eht nrut I litnu niaga em redro nac ydobon dna ffo si ppa eht esuaceb syawyna rettam t’nseoD
,liar eht no kcaB
.ti ni mrah eht ees t’ndid I tub
em ot txen taes a sekat eH
.yadot dias sah nwaD tnua ym sgniht yzarc tahw swonk ohW
.tnemtrapa sih fo hcni erauqs yreve rettil
,musssopo erih-rof-xes a
esuac ,’nihton ro tnemilpmoc eht deen I taht ton s’tI
,tnemom siht ta thgir dna ,lufituaeb dias eH
edir siht no setunim erom ytriht tuoba tog ev’eW
,lap ,em deredro uoY
.spil eht no thgir mih gnissik
,redluohs sih ot stfihs wap yM
,flesym yojne ot derevocsid I hcihw fo emos ,sgniht enod ev’I ,wonk tsuJ
.em ta kcab gnirats ecaf railimaf a s’ti
,tuo snaom dna kcab daeh sih sworht eh
,ylsuoituac revo gnihcaeR
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,llew ,esuac mih fo dloh barg ot drah adnik s’tI .edis
.ti rof hguod eht tog ev’uoy fi
?tsafkaerb emos ro eeffoc rof tuo og ot mih ecnivnoc nac I ebyaM
,esnetni ytterp neeb ev’tsum msagro yM
.ereht s’eh taht rednimer gnitrofmoc a tsuj tub ,duol ton s’tI
.daeh ym kcoc dna enohp ym fo gniD railimaf eht raeh I nehw ni ti nrut ot ydaer tuoba m’I
,su fo owt eht rof deb siht no moor hguone ylerab
tsuj ot doog sleef dna yad lla pu tnep adnik neeb ev’I
.ti ekil leef adnik I
.stneilc ruo dna keew ruo tuoba klat ot thgin yadsendeW yreve puteem sdutS rehto net tuoba dna eM
.raeh ot stnaw eh tahw yltcaxe s’tI .eil I
,ppa eht pu nepo I nehw ,yllufknahT
.raeh ot evol lla d’yeht onihr hcni owt a tuoba yrots a tog I meht gnillet puorg ym ot txet a toohs dna tops ym ot kcab teg I
htaerb ruo dna eno semoceb gnitnap ruO .esool tel
em sllet elahni prahs A
sevlesruo no edam ssem eht ees eW
.eno on ’nitruh t’nia eh dna
,hsinif I emit eht yb dna ,gnipleh dnoces a rof em deredro tsuj yob yxoF .thgiR
.esulcer a fo dnik s’eh tub
.ssik eht gnidloh elihw
.dlob oot gnieb morf dehsaba
emas eht no elpoep ynam oot tcejer I fi tihs em evig lliw ppa ehT
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna eseht piks nac uoy
,eromyna em ta kool ot elba ton s’eH
.taes ym fo tuo teg yletaidemmi t’nod tub
.moor ym ot kcab og dna desserd teg tsuj nac I taht gnikniht
.sseug I ,yadot yad ysuB
.thginot ereht tuo kcab gniog m’I yaw on yletulosba s’ereht dna yad
.htnom a tsael ta rof thgiarts yadyreve ananab a htiw decitcarp s’eh litnu
.epaga wam sih htiw gnirats
.rae ym ni gnirons s’eh erofeb setunim elpuoc a naht regnol hcum tsal t'nseod eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
dnoces a rof ylno trap ot evah eW
.hcuoc ym no tuoba egnuol ot emoh daeh dna ppa eht ffo nrut annog tsuj m’I neht ,yad ym hguorht yawflah kaep I fI
.launam noitcurtsni na htiw emac eh ekil nwod dna pu yug siht daer nac I dna cilbup ni tuo er’ew tub
—dna em naht rellams s’eH
.ma I ffo dessip woh edih yllaer t’nac I esuac
,tab eht ffo thgiR
.nwod mih nrut attog I
.naelc flesym peek ot drah yllaer yrt I ,yllausU
?thgir ,stnuoc adnik taht os gnidliub emas eht ni m’I ,yllacinhcet
.thgirla eb ton dluow ti on ,hguoht dnoceS
.tnelis gniniamer elihw pu rehto hcae gnirehtal emit ruo ekat ew dna od eW
.poc a llaC .thguac neeb ev’I
tsuj uoY .sknaht on tub ,sknahT“
.elbissop sa ylteercsid sa ni pils dna nepo rood eht edils I
,tlep kciht sih otni swalc ym gniggid dna pil ym gnitiB
.pots ot mih geb attog I dna elzzum sih ni retarg eseehc a tog s’eh raewS !em toN
si eh sa dren a fo gib sa tsuj m’I tub
dna hguoht ssenisub ym fo enon s’tahT
?ydaerla skeew owt neeb yllaer ti sah ,ym ym hO
.kcid gib a hcus tog ev’uoy
.ffo gniht nmad eht nrut ot togrof I ,tinraD
.tsaf dna trohs era sekorts ym dna tfahs sih dnuora nori si pirg yM
reven ot sesimorp eh taht egnahcxe ni daeh mih evig I
ffuts stropsretaw emos htiw yad ym hsinif I
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“   :yojne esaelP
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb