,dedliub era htaed fo setag eht erehw ,srevir neves fo dnal eht nI
dednuofnoc flesruoy evah uoY !ymene
era ereht enon dnA
?regna ym enihstuo lliw ti tahT
,erifpmac sih fo srebme eht yB ,srebme eht yb ylno detfil thgindim tsepeed eht ni erehT
”,uoy tsniaga denrut evah flesruoy uoy nevaeh fo nus eht dloheB
htaed fo setag eht erehw
.mih setaerc taht dna ,setaerc eh thgilyad eht nihtiw stsixe eH“
”.rehtaf gniraeb-gninrom ym fo
,floWcaM boR yb
,murudO mirg hteraews oS
.ecneitap fo kaeps dluow ,ereh eh erew
.srebme eht ot derepsihw neroC
,neroC ni derrits gnihtemos yas yehT
neroC neve ton yas yeht dnA
.mih etims ot dog-regna eht rof detiaw dna
,noitarepooc-non dna ,ytineres ,tnemnethgilnE
,sradeC eht gnomA thgiN eht nI“
.sseug a tub si taht tuB
.deusrup I ma llits dnA ,dehsinav dna tsol si nalc ym lla dna ,nials si rehtorb-doolb yM
,gninrom eht tsniaga dial I evaH gninruom fo seirutnec ynam woH
,gnivil era sevil latrom eht erehw ,srevir neves fo dnal eht morF
,uratnamahsI kniht I“
,sehcnarb radec hguorht srats eht dna
.yad yreve nevaeh fo htap sih deklaw eh sA
efink sih demlap neroC
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
nosaer dleh-traeh eht kaeps nac dna ,rewsna nac neroC kniht od I
,selttab yttep yrrac ton ll’I
repsihW neroC did tsal tA
)detfil era sduolc nehw syad eht no ti ees nac I( niatnuom a sdnatS
.sradec eht woleb krad eht ni
,snevaeh eht ssorc yenruoj sekam eh yliad nehw flesmih ot sknihT
yojne esaelP  .egap yrruFoS sih no
).snevaeh eht fo tsehgih eht ni uratnamahsI ot yrolG(
,snevaeh eht otni niaga ecnO mih esiar ot nwad fo lwoh eht rof ssenkrad eht ni detiaw eh erehW
”.reven em edaussid llahs uoy secnaegnev desoprup ym morf dnA
!ti etsat lliw uoy dna eman tub deen uoy ,evah dluow uoy ecnaegnev tahW ,ssendam ym morf em ekawa did cisum s’rehtaF eht tsrif ecniS em desaelp os sah gnihton roF
neroC rerednaw latrom eht emaC
.neroC latrom ma I tuB
.noitanimircer ruod a si daehdog otni em tfil seod tahT ,gnikaerb thgil s’nwad fo lwoh eht rof
gnixev gnitsalreve
,rof deyarteb uoy dna demehcs uoy nos eht dloheb ,naloraB hO“ ,amgam eht morf htesira taht duolc htaed citsalcoryp eht ekiL
.snevaeh eht ssorca htap sih sdaert uratnamahsI niaga erehW
eye sih yam ,regna dednet-reve eht fO(
revir eht naht rehtruf ynA ,sreicalg gnivigrofnu eht fo niatnuom eht derad ton evah I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
gnikees eht ni netfo dnA
.ti yned ot rehtob ton oD .uratnamahsI
,swodahs tub neeb evah thgim eh erehw ,thgilerif gnillud-erutaef eht nI thgilerif eht ni neroC derewsna
”!regnA sseldnE fo eye ym yb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
)niatnuom eht fo traeh peed eht ekil ,ssenkrad eht ni denrub eye sih dnA(
,nmutua eht ni drahcro eht ni stenroh neknurd fo muh ekiL ,gnidaf thgilerif eht ssorca morf yltfos emac eciov s’murudO
),su nopu ton nrut
tneicna yM“ dehgual eh dnA
saw sihT     .dedliub era
.sreicalg enitsirp ni speels ti dna ,teiuq s’ti syadawon hguohtlA ,esirnus eht tuo stolb ekoms sti dna
,sradeC eht gnomA thgiN eht nI“
,yks eht morf em hctaw uoy wonk I“ dias eh dnA
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,niatnuom eht fo seenk hguor eht no tserof detsim-reve eht oT
,tneitap eb tsum uoy ,nus eht htiw ytimne yna evah uoy fI“
,retaw eht no enihsnus eht ekil
,hsirehc uoy draeh syawla evah I eutriv a si ecneitap dnA
uratnamahsI thgirB tahw swonk
,anosrep a dna ksam a sa rehto eht raew eht seod eno eht tuB .neroC oreh eht ton si eH
,srevir neves fo dnal revO
”,uratnamahsI ton ma I“
murudO no )yas selat eht os ro( dekool uratnamahsI thgirB ,detfil erew sduolc nehw syad eht no ,sreicalg eht no enohs nus eht nehW
,thgindim eht ni ecnelis saw erehT
.ehtaerb ot derad erutaerc gnivil a ton erehW
latnedicnioc ylbaborp si
,lufdaerd saw ti ,ecnaegneV fo drol ,murudO
!ymene yht ekil retteb seoD“
),hsirehc seod eh taht ,draeh evah I ,eutriv a si ecneitap dnA(
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,senigami daeh deolah ruoy taht ssenkrad fo drol eht ton ma I
,gninrom eht litnu tsael tA
,sreicalg eht htaeneb peelsa tsaf
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,seitied htiw llet nac reven uoy tub
),regna gnitsalreve sih htiw gnizalb tserof eht stes ohW(
”,ylmid ylno rebmemer dnA rebmemer uoy taht maerd a morf gnikaw sa si mih eb ot roF
”!rof deksa evah dluoc regna gnitsalreve ym naht ylerus eroM
”niatnuoM eht fo retlehS eht nI
.srevir neves fo dnal eht ni
)egasiv sih erofeb delf evah dluow neroC naht ssel oreh A(
,sreicalg enitsirp morf nwod sraor taht
.sreicalg ym naht retihw neve ,subminolumuc skaep eht nO detteuohlis uoy nees evah I
kaeps ton lliw I(
),detfil era sduolc nehw syad no ecnanetnuoc sih fo ssenthgirb eht ,hO(
enotsmirb stimov ti yas yehT
!latrommi latrom ,no yaS“
meop a uoy gnidaer m’I yadoT dna
!siht enod dah I ylno fI
?thgilnus eht raef I kniht uoy oD
,nosaer eht wonk od straeh rieht tub ,ti kees ohw
.tserof detsim eht hguorht gniraor
murudO ot noititep yam ti sbmilc ohw eh taht yas yehT
”.ecnaegneV ot yas ot sdrow
,yrolg fo ezalb a ecaf sih htiw
evah dluow thgilnuS yloH fo dog eht yhW
.niatnuom eht fo sllihtoof eht ot
,niatnuom ruoy nopu skool eh nehW gnikniht eb yam eh sthguoht eht fo od uoy naht erom on wonk I dnA .daehdog otni delbmuts I ecnis dessentiw ton ev’I thgilyad eht nI
.esirnuS ylenol eht wonk ton od I
,ssenkrad tcefrep ylraen eht ni neroC revo detaolg eH
eht morF modeerf ot gniht tseraen eht si ecnaegnev taht eb tey yam tI
)retlews ylsselitip yam ro ,suoyoj eb yam taht nus eht ekiL(
.reverof em dednuoh sah eH
,”niatnuoM eht fo retlehS eht nI
”.nekops eb yam rehto eht yb gnikniht si eno taht sdrow dnA
.uratnamahsI lliw ron yan ,segdurg elituf sih thgif ton ll’I
,dedliub era htaed fo setag eht erehW ,tserof ytsim eht hguorht sraor taht
revir gnigar-reve eht nahT
”.em tageb eh taht lla rof ton
,mih laecnoc ot ssenkrad eht htiw
”!uoy tsniaga dellifluf lluf lla secnaegnev ym tnuoc I dluoc nehT
fo rethgual eht hO
,nmutua fo sthgin ylrae eht ni snretnal eht fo taeh llud ekiL
,mih defashcuov secnaegnev fo ymene sih sesimorp tahW ,mih tsniaga repsihw derad latrommi nos latrom sih stolp tahW rednow tsum eh taht sseug dluow I meht draeh sah naloraB fI ).ylfeirb ylno detfil era yeht detfil era sduolc eht fi dnA ,detfil era sduolc nehw syad eht no niatnuom eht ees ylno nac enO(
,noitadnuof s’ssertrof a nihtiw senots ekil dehcnelc hteet neewteB
.tnelis llaf selat eht ereh tuB
lufdaerd saw eh dna ,erif eht ediseb nwod mih tas murudO ”.nosaer eht tub lla esol yeht od
floWcaM boR yb meop a
,uoy llet ton dluoc I flesym roF
).erbmit sti ton nrael srae ruo yam ,su hcaer reven ohce sti yaM(
,sreicalg eht sa enitsirp dna sselitip saw elims lufdaerd siH
,niatnuom ym no era seye gnignol s’uratnamahsI fi oS ,neroC latrom htiw traeh a serahs uratnamahsI fi oS“
”.hsinav lliw I mih otni nehw
,ecitsuj ton sah ohw eh dnA
.snoitpo ssel evah slatrom ew dnA
,amgam ekil ecaf sih til taht thgilerif eht ni detluxe eH
,regna gnitsalreve eht fo murudO ot dercas si tahT
,neroC ot emoc murudO diD
daed ro gnivil seitied ot ecnalbmeser yna taht ezisahpme ot sehsiw ohw
gnineve eht ni dnA
.ssenkrad radec eht htaeneb evag murudO ot neroC tahT rewsna eht llet nac eno toN
.rehtaf ym ,naloraB“
).tserof gniraor taht nihtiw was I tahw fo
.mih nopu yhtapme htiw skool regnA sseldnE fo droL eht fI ecnaegnev dnif tsael ta yam eh ereht
.uratnamahsI ton era uoY“
,niatnuom ym degamirglip evah sreppihsrow ynaM“ ,murudO diaS
revir eht naht rehtruf ynA ti bmilc ot derad reven evah I