,tnilf eht nwod thguorb anaS
”?rellevart a htiw erif ruoy erahS“
?eno siht nommus uoy diD“
.niaga yks eht otni pu dezag eh sa tiaw dluoc taht
,desaeced ylwen eht ot eybdoog yas ot devreser ylnommoc erutseg A
.thgilnoom eht ni detteuohlis seert rif eht
.stirips eht fo dlrow eht dna
.lworg trohs a htiw mih deppots enirevlow ehT
.meht dnatsrednu ot ,meht ees ot
.deffocs flow eht
.triks ypparcs ,trohs sih yb
-tuohtiw od ekam ot nrael ot evah d’eh gniht rehtona tsuj saw siht ,hceeps ekil dna
.nwo sti no sselesU
.mih revo seert eht detfil ezeerb ehT
seye deroloc norffas siH
.efink gnol eht ot txen tleb sih morf gnuh reviuq
,reffo dnik a hcus tcejer ot edur neeb evah dluow ti dnA
,sngis ni meht evig ot deirt anaS nehw naht
.edis ruoy no yleritne ma I ,dneirf ,htrow si ti tahw roF“
,erif nrobwen eht nopu yltneg gniwolb dna wol gnipoots
,efink enob sih fo dne eht no ti gnireweks
.wap rehtie ni sehcuop rehtael fo riap a ,txeN
,raef eht retlehS .thguoht anaS
,kcab sih ssorca gnuls woB
.enots nedlog eht tsniaga eparcs daeh detniop sti tel
,tnemom a rof seert eht dnuora gnar
.llew yreV“ .deddon anaS
.sdnik lla fo stiripS
.wap rehto sih ni tnilf eht gnipsarg
,ti htiw werg edirp fo esnes A
.thgin gnirewol eht ni
.kcap pu dellor eht fo parts eht revo morf dna
mih ot meht EKOPS enoemos nehw snoitanalpxe dnatsrednu ot elba erom on demees ohw
.deknilb flow ehT ”.sih s’tI“
,enod eb ot gniht eno tub si ereht nehw taht
,ti otni llaf dluoc eh fi sa
skraps gnihtees yniT
,hteet sih tirg retto ehT
.dedneffo mees t’ndid ,tsael ta ,enirevlow ehT
,gnillac sih saw ti tuB
,tserof eht ni ,ereh tuO
.ti od ot si gniht ylno ehT
.ereht esle eno on saw ereht dias evah dluow
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
,ecnatsid eht otni dedaf
,nwod tas eh ereht dnA
.skraps eht htrof nommus ot noitatnacni kciuq a dereffo evah dluow eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.nihtiw seilppus eht dna kcap sih ta nwod kool tub pleh t’ndluoc eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.meht ta detuohs tsuj uoY
,t’ndluoc eh ebyam rO .ebyaM
,ylprahs os denoh eb ylno dluoc sesnes s’eno
,erif eht dliub ,sucof ot dah eH
.si taht drah woh gninialpmoc ni tniop on si ereht
.enirevlow eht ta tsif a detniop neht
ereh tuo enola t’nsaw eh erus eb dluoc eh naem did ti tuB
,tbuod a tuohtiw ,driB
,sredir dna sretnuh rof erew snoitacovnI
,nethgit spil sih
,ssenkcis hcihw laeh dluoc stnalp hcihw fo sterces eht wenk dna
.eson sih htaeneb dessap
tuo denword lla saw ti ,yllautnevE
.regnarts yldneirf a yb detcartsid teg t’nod os ,dias noitiutni s’anaS ,ybraen erehwemos tirips lufrewop yrev a llits s’erehT
,erab tsehc ,llat ,flow A
,hctap yrrebkcalb a ni gniyl noonretfa eritne na tneps dah
,ywenis dna ynniks
,ereh gniteem desoporp I nehw ,thguoht t’ndah I
tniop eht tsap gnolruf tneced a tnew eH
.esu ot nrael nac uoy rehto yna ekil ,loot a si raef
.thgilrats eht ni delkniwt taht enots nedlog fo eceip hguor dna
selat llat gnillet seciov duorp eht dna smurd eht fo mhtyhr citnarf eht
:ihovatneL wollef sih ekil ,klat llams dna seirtnasaelp ni degludni evah dluow eh
.nruter ni mih tcetorp yam ti taht os ,worg ti tel dna
.llik ysae na hcus ekam ot detiaw evah t’ndluow tsitluc a
,stnirpwap s’ebirt sih htiw detniap sredluob eht htaeneb dna ,sknurt rif eht ni spag eht hguorht
,ssenkrad ylno yal erifpmac sih fo arua gniwolg eht dnoyeB
,esruoc fO !flesruoy wohS
.mih htiw syawla eb ot thguo stirips ehT
,uoy ekirts lliw enim fo dnah on taht“
.meht dleiw ot dnim prahs a tuohtiw
tnemom gnissap yrevE .rebma krad fo
.ksa ot woh wenk dna
.retnilps ytsan a htiw bmuht sih raeps ot denetaerht dna
.erif sih gnidliub krow ot tes anaS elihw tiaw ot evah d’yeht
,semalf otni tsrub thgil egnaro gniredloms eht sA
,kaeps dluoc anaS fI
gnoht tug tibbar a htiw deit dna niksreed ni depparw edalb
.anaS etisoppo erif eht yb tis ot edam eH
dlrow tirips eht rof ytiniffa na koot ti ,oot ,spahreP
,lufecaep erom neve wohemos pmac eht morf ecnatsid dna edutilos edam thgiN
,yadot ylno dellik
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
,od dluoc eh tseb eht saw tI
gnirehtag tuo tnew ohw enoyreve
.dluoc eh fi ,flesmih ot derettum evah dluow anaS
mih neewteb ecnereffid eht tuo ekam dluoc anaS erofeb deedni esolc yrev teg ot dah eh taht os
?thgir ,truh t’ndluoc noitcartsid elttil a ,lleW
.psarg sih ni yalc tew ekil demrofed stnetnoc sti ,tfos saw enO
?fo kaeps uoy gniteem siht s’tahw dnA
derewol eh ylwolS
,s’enirevlow eht naht repeed neve tub regnuoy dna remraw
”.gniod ym fo enon saw tI
’,klaT tonnaC I tub ,nwod tiS ,esaelp seY‘
.eye deniartnu eht ot elbitpecrepmi yletelpmoc saw hcihw gnihtemoS
:eruliaf fo tol a dna ,ecitcarp koot
,sgnitniaP evaC mlohsiauQ fo yevruS laitinI“
.ti htiw tsehc sih morf ssenthgit eht tuo dehtaerb
regnuoy neeb d’eh nehw tub
nik rieht fo erom sderdnuh yb denioj
.dloheb ylpmis ot tnetnoc saw eh tnemom a roF
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.ksa ot elba eb ot retteb leef anaS edam evah dluow llits tI
,lleweraf fo erutseg a saw ti thguoht I“
.eurtnu ylpmis saw taht tuB
,elims etilop a dereffo enirevlow eht sa
sselesu era yeht tub
,deveileb eb ot erew seirots fi ,hguohT
’.diaS tsuJ I gnihT eht yaS ot woh knihT ot gniyrT tsuj saw I ,suoicipsuS t’nsaW I‘
gnosdrib reppihc htaeneb
.niaga daeherof sih no sregnif owt sih decalp eh sa
,naidisbo ylraelc saw ti tfah eht ffo tnilg eht morf tub
savnac gnidaf eht hguorht enihs ot nugeb dah taht srats wef eht devresbo ylluferac anaS ,yks eht ni pU
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ruf degnis dna ,selkcunk dekcarc ,sregnif decils
.thgir s’anaS ot elttil a kcor a otno delttes dna
yb tnew syad eht nehw oS ’.gnihton gniod‘
,dna sregnif sih neewteb gnivaew dnuos eht
,derussaer eb naht rehtar tuB
,thgilerif fo elcric eht fo stimil eht ta tsuj doots eH
.syaw sih dah namahs retto eht tub
mih dehctaw yeht spahreP
,sluos neesnu fo rennam lla erew ereht
,ylprahs ,ecno htrof dna kcab dnah sih deppohc neht
,ekirts tcefrep eht edam eh erusne ot sgniws ecitcarp wef a gnikat
.rehctub delliks a yb derettab ydob rieht
htgnerts sih ti evig dluow eH
.lla retfa ,dlrow siht fo yleritne ton gniht a saw erif—
,erif eht fo edis rehto eht ot derutseg anaS
,llew ,ihovatneL eht htiw esu dluow eh sngis ehT
,ewA uoy sehcaet tI
,uoy llet dluow ihovatneL yna sa ,tnecs dna—
.kcap llams eht otni kcab devled dna edis sih ta ti deppord anaS
,thgir rehcaet sih devorp dna
.dias eson s’anaS ,taem hserF
,luos yna ekil dnA .luos ylno
,elzzum sih ot swap deppuc sih desiar anaS sa
.seert rif eht deltsur ti sa dniw eht fo enord eltbus eht dna
,htaerb gnol a werd anaS
.anaS htiw tnaw yeht tahw dna
.retteb wenk anaS
.ti deen ot ton thguo eH
,taht ot emoc t’ndluow ti yllufepoH
,eltsihw ot nageb dna spil sih desrup retto eht ,gniwolB
yas ot yaw rehtona tsuj saw
,deliaf yeht fi dnA
.ti no tas uoy ecno leef tub pleh t'ndluoc uoy tub
esnopser fo kcal eht
,uoy erujni lliw enim fo nopaew on taht
seirrebkcalb epir fo roloc eht ruf
,enirevlow dlo nA
.sdrow sih htiw enilced yletilop ton dluoc eh sa yllaicepse
.kcen sih fo kcab eht hsurb stirips eht fo raef eht tlef dah eh erehw
.traeh gninrub eht dnuora elip a ni ti gnilbmessa ylkciuq dna doowerif hcrib eht barg ot dnuora gnihcaer
,dias dah rehcaet sih sA
nekcarb eht ni dih taht erah ehT
tsug gnorts a tlef eh
rof serutseg yna evah t’ndid eh emahs A
,ecap eht pu gnikciP
,sehcnarb hcrib elttirb fo eldnub a :doowerif ,tsriF
ruop dna hcuop wollat eht ekat neht
.worht ot skcor syawla erew ereht
.daeh sih evoba hgih
,delzzis ti elihw
pmac eht fo gnorht eht erofeb gnol t’nsaw tI
,ti no yltneg ehtaerb
,kcap sih morf nosinev fo pirts a rof gnihcaeR
ekil gnihtemos naem ot deterpretnisim eb t’ndluoc
.gnildnik eht nopu taf gnillems-tneluccus eht fo reyal niht a
.stnetnoc sti hguorht egammur ot nageb dna
.regnuh s’anaS dias
,oga syad evlewt etiuq toN
,namahs a rof yllaicepse ,gnuoy llits saw eh ,llew—
,flow eht dias ”!hO“
.dnatsrednu dluoc enon syaw ni dekrow dna elbisivni dna elbawonknu erew stiripS
”.ydaerla ereh eb thgim esle enoyna taht
redluohs sih revo morf kaolc niksreed eht dekrihs retto ehT
”…dnatsrednu ton od I“
.elbatrofmoc flesmih edam dna
.retnuh doog yna ekil
stsug eht ot desopxe tfel sgel sih
wap deraems-wollat sih sa delbmurg taht hcamots a htiw ysub saw eno siht dna
”?yhtapme sih tuohtiw
,daeherof sih no sregnif owt decalp anaS
.ylper oN .dedaf neht
anaS thguoht ,luos sih tser stiripS
,redrah neve ta dekool gnieb er’uoy ekil leef uoy esruoc fO
,nagimratp ro esuorG
,tserof derrits-dniw eht ,tesnus eht tsuJ
?morf emoc uoy od erehW
uoy sehcaet ti dnA
dekool ti taht ytuaeb sseldne dna tsav hcum os
srewop neesnu eht dnA
tnilf fo eceip a deveirter dna tleb sih rof dehcaer neht retto eht
.spil derruf krad desrup flow ehT
.nus gnittes eht dnuora sduolc eht ekil dewolg tsomla yeht tniop eht ot thgilerif eht pu kaos ot demees
”cihtiloseM reppU demuserp ,nwonknU nigirO
,ssap dluow ti depoh dah anaS
.sgol dlo ni gnidih stcesni fo prihc dna muh eht yb decalper
evila mih hctac dluoc uoy fi
,nam yna si erehw ,namahs a si erehW
.ylevitcepser eno hcae dezeeuqs eH
.eipgam ro worc a fo
tnilf eht desiar eh ,nehT
,nediw seye sih ekam ot desaec reven
:krab dna yks eht ot elzzum retto suoblub sih esiar ot detnaw yldab os eH
:on mih thguat dah
.ylevitcepser gnildnik dna wollaT
”.ecnahc erup yb ereh saw eH“
,sgnitniaP evaC mlohsiauQ fo yevruS laitinI“
.stirips eht dehcaorppa eh nehw traeh sih no dial llits raef regnif eno taht fo demahsa neeb d’eh ,gninrael dna—
,gnildnik eht revo enots nedlog egnarts eht denoitisop eH
’.suoicileD eB lliW senoB ruoY fo worraM eht epoH I‘
.mih erofeb tuo dehcterts htap eht dnA
,pmac eht raeh regnol on dluoc eh erehw
.htuom nepo sih ssorca
.dnatsrednu dluow enirevlow eht yllufepoH
,elzzum sih ot ti gnignirB
.pu dekool dna mlac ot flesmih decrof eh neht
tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.gnirts wenis a yb rehtegot deit
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
tnecs nwo sih ot dnuorgkcab ylno eht tserof fo llems eht
.yks gnineve yreif eht ni gnuh ti sa noom eht ta pu gnirats
,ytisnetni ni worg ot demees yeht
.seye sih fo skcab eht ffo detnilg erif eht taht elgna thgir eht tsuj ta anaS gnihctaw
.enirevlow eht detcejretni
”’,uoY knahT‘ snaem eH“
,edis a dah eh kniht t’ndid eh
,era sregnarts suoiretsym eseht ohw
.tsif a dednetxe dna
”,neht ,seigolopa yM“
.ksa ot dah ohw esoht
,enots nedlog eht dna tnilf eht htob deppord eh
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
.neewteb ni secaps eht dna htaed dna efil fo
.thguorb d'eh nosinev deird eht naht laem tneluccus erom hcum a
,htiw maercs ot eugnot eht kcal uoy nehw ysae taht reve saw gnihton
gnuoy neeb d’eh nehW .detatiseh eH
skao derevoc-ssom eht ni tlewd ohw esohT
.tserof eht nopu delttes thgin sa
.erif eht revo ti tnuom ot kcits enip a deneprahs eh sa
.ereh tirips lufrewop a saw erehT
.gnihton gniyps dna
leuf eht ekat ti tel
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sdrawkcab delttucs anaS
,gnorts werg semalf eht feiler sih oT
,feiler htiw gnihgiS
,eciov wen a dias ”,yhw dnA“
.ffihw a koot anaS
”?semit ta ecnardnih a ti t’nsI“
.wenk ydobon noitamrofni emos rof dna
,ydob a tuohtiw tub
.enirevlow eht ta ,ylyls ,decnalg eH
pal sih ni ti decalp eH
”.ytilatipsoh ruoy rof sknaht sA .ekat ,esaelP“
,pil sih tib anaS ,lleW
,meht wonk ot ,krow sih
.kcap sih morf gnihtemos dellup enirevlow ehT
.seye gniwonk ,prahs htiw laem sih morf pu gnicnalg saw ohw
”?sey ,sdrow ym dnatsrednu tey nac uoy tub ,kaeps tonnac uoy ,oS“
ylluflliks os erif a ekirts oT .tug sih ni
”,eno on denommus I“
”.desaeced eht rof
”cihtiloseM reppU demuserp ,nwonknU nigirO
,dehcnurc ,deltsur rehto ehT
nekcarb tfos htaenrednu kcor a ekiL
”?ecnardnih a eb reve yhtapme dluow“
,ereht tuo erew stirips revetahW
,sesnes sih neprahs pleh dluow ti spahreP
.sremmus wef tsal eht revo tserof eht ni deraeppa dah taht stsitluc suoirav eht fo mih dednimer daeh sih fo kcab eht ni eciov elttil eht ,gniwonk ton retteb saw ti spahreP
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ngis a saw ti spahreP
,ebyam ,ebirt sih fo srehtO
.stirips eht rof gnihtyna edisa gnittes tuohtiw tfel dah neht dna ,llif sih gnitae
,daeherof sih ot sregnif owt dehcuot
.yrd dna sseletsat ylluf seirreb eht lla dnuof dah
,gnignis deppots dah sdrib ehT
.ereht tlewd taht stirips eht dna dlrow tirips eht raef ot elbadnatsrednu saw ti
.eb ot tnaem t’ndah eH .hguone lleW
.anaS ta syawedis deddon eH ”.erif ym t’nsI“
.detnarg rof ecnedicnioc a ekat ot reven denrael dah eh dna
.meht gnoma deklaw ohw namahs enol eht nopu dexif seye rieht
,ihovatneL gnuoy eht fo eno
.retniaf dna retniaf emaceb
,erus eb ot ,elbanosaer saw tI
.mih dniheb sllih eht til tesnus ehT  2 fo 1 traP ,emanrohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“   yojne esaelP
.decar dnim s’anaS
.srats eht rof tlef eh tahw ekil gnihtemos ot pu ezalb dluow ti dna
.tsehc sih ni pael traeh sih dna
”,gnihtyna snaem taht fi sA“
.ewA fo yoJ eht dna
.feihc eno fo etaf elbirret eht llacer tub pleh t’ndluoc dnim s’anaS
yas ot esu ot tuoba saw eh serutseg eht erus eb ot deen dluow eH
,ees t'ndluoc uoy taht
,otni raef sih worg ot mih rof tnaem dah rehcaet sih tahw ylbaborp saw tahT
.regnarts dnuofwen siht morf
.t’ndluoc eh taht llew sa tsuj saw ti os
,evac a ni dnuof neeb dah yeht ,retniw tsal ylno saw tI
,gninrom txen ehT
eltsihw eht fo seohce llirhs ehT
sredluohs sih morf tfil thgiew a tlef namahs ehT
,tneinevnoc ylniatrec saw gnimit ehT
”.stseug ruoy erew ew ezilaer ton did I“
niaga flesmih dnuora gnikool
,regnarts eht ta pu kcab gnicnalG
.tnecs nwo sti dah ti
.ti dnuora depparw smra sih htiw
,gnildnik dekaos-taf eht otni taps
’gnipoh‘ ,mih dlot ecno dah rehcaet sih sa ,neht tub
.erofeb sA .htap eht
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.nettog dah ti krad woh tsuj desilaer anaS taht yks thgin eht drawot esir ot nageb semalf eht sa ylno saw tI
ecnelis tneitap ni detiaw
ylevitpecrep deddon eH
.deffins enirevlow eht
,dlrow yranidro eht neewteb seil redrob eht erehw uoy swohs tI
.sessih dna selkcarc yppah htiw hcrib eht gniruoved
,flow kcalb eht drawot daeh sih denilcni eh …sselehtenon tub
regae oot kool ot ton luferac saw eH
.segap yrruFoS evitcepser rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,won flesmih stirips eht gnoma enog ,rehcaet sih tuB
.tneserp yllausu t'nsaw taht enO
.doof rieht otni dekcut htob yeht sa dnuorg eht ot llaf ezag sih tel yllanif dna
.laem thgin sih mraw ot ti esu neht
.erom neve gnihtemos saw ereht won thgir tuB
”,namahs a rof ,gnorts si yhtapme ruoY“
.lwo na fo llac ylenol eht htiw ria eht gnillif ,cigam ekil
.meht ezingocer ton thgim regnarts a
.eirever sih detpurretni eciov yerg derit a ”,liaH“
,enirevlow eht detnemmoc
,lamina yna ekil tsuj ,dlo werg ,eta
gnikaorc esraoc eht yb nekorb ylerar ecaep eht—luoS eht saw
,ereh tuo enola tlef evah tsomla dluoc eH
,ylthgils daeh sih gniwob ,oS
,kaeps dluoc eh fI
,erus rof yas ot namahS a nekat evah dluow tI .ton spahreP
.ruf retto keels sih revo hsur
,dehtaerb ,devil tI
.mih dniheb thgin eht dna
.anaS ot dias eh
,noitcif evitaroballoc seldnah tsacdop siht woh gnitset era ohw
.meht raeH ot elba eb ot hguone ,ykculnu ro ,ykcul esoht ot ro ,rehtohcae ot dniW eht ni repsihW dluoc ohw dna
.yrassecen ton saw ti dne eht nI
,epacsrats eht fo thgis ehT
.yltnatsni tsomla thgila thguac hcihw
,kooc ot erif eht sdrawot tuo ti gnidloh
,flesmih tuoba decnalg retto eht sA
.tahwemos detapissid ruf sih ni noisnet eht dna
.gnihtemos od ot tuo tes d’eh
,yletarebiled ,ylwolS .derutroT
.elpoep emos ot ssorca ffuts teg dluoc eh yaw ylno eht saw ecnetsisnI
,mra sih desiar dna
?eman ruoy s’tahW
,trid ynots eht otno hcuop rednit eht morf ssarg yrd eht fo emos pit
.sknaht evig ot ti esu ot emoc dah anaS tub
lesaew elttil sseldeeh taht ,athonU
.taht wonk ylerus dluow stirips eht dna
taem eht koot retto eht
.kaolc hguor dna tah daorb
,noituac rof esuap sih gnikatsim yltnerappa ,dias enirevlow eht ”,raews lliw I“
,esnet ydob elohw sih tlef anaS
.tserof eht revo gnignah ecneserp fo esnes eht
,htolchceerb dna sgniggel krad
,kaeps dluoc eh fi dettimda evah dluow anaS ,ewa otni denrut yllaer reven dah raef ehT
,ydob sih dnuora rethgit kaolc niks reednier eht dellup dna derevihs anaS
.hsigguls uoy sekam ti yas dluow sretnuh eht hguoht
,degaussa naht rehtar ,desaercni
.yciuj ylerus dna pmulp
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
”.sruoy fo gniht yna hcuot llahs enim fo tfeht on taht