,yks thgin eht flah gnirevoc niar tfos fo steehs saw ti litnu seert gniltsur eht hguorht gnisir
dnif dluow selpoep retal emos
.yllufreehc yrev ,detnemmoc renruoM
”.tser ot ecalp hguone efas a era smra ym dlot neeb evah I tuB
?yas ot evah ew tahw htiw no teg“
.sdnal eseht fo selpoep eht gnoma ,eman on evah …I“
,noitagorretni na ekil tlef tI
,doots renruoM ”,tey ton evah I“
”,rof emac ew tahw ton si tahT“
,niatnuom a fo ezis eht
,ti retne gnihtemos tlef eh esuaceb
,enola tserof krad eht otni tuo emoc dah eh nosaer eht ,scitna hsifles sih dna athonU ,esruoc fO
.ssensseleulc sih dna namahs eht no ytip ekat ot gnimees
stseug sih fo hcae ta decnalg eh sa redluohs sih gnibbur ylsuovren
,evreserp ot hguone dercas meed dna
.dedneffo erew stirips hcihw wonk neve t’ndid eH
sniks detaert tsuj
.kcohs ni ecaf sih ot deppalc tsuj d’eh swap eht fo eno htiw detset eh
,tnurg railimaf-gnol a ylno deganam dna
”?eman sih wonk ot hsiw uoY“ .dibrof stirips
,dootsrednu dah yeht fi neve tuB
.ylluferac sdrow nwo sih redisnoc ot dah eh desilaer anaS
”…taht ,neht ,kniht uoy oD“
”.renruoM em llac yam uoy nehT“ ,flow eht dias
,stserof dna senob fo gninrub eht dna
,stirips eht tsniaga dettimmoc namsebirt gnuoy a tcepsersid eht sserder ot ssenredliw eht otni tuo deyenruoj
,ruf s’flow fo llems eht tuB
.snoitnetni eurt rieht gnidih eb yam yeht taht ngis yna ot tnaligiv
,gnihtemos morf eerht eseht dibrof ot detnaw irutiÄ fi...
”!yrt lliw I dna ,lufepoh ma I“
,eson sih fo egdirb eht dehcnip eh sa anaS dehgis
.segap yrruFoS evitcepser rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.elkcuhc detraeh-flah s’retto eht gninruter
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
?noitanalpxe na rof namahs tnelis eht gniksa ni ereht saw tniop tahw neht
,selggurts ruoy ot hcaorppa suoicanet ruoy htiw ,uoY“
.renruoM ta yldetniop dekool rekaepS
,dias evah t’ndluoc eh hguoht
.ezag evitisiuqni na htiw desiar worbeye sih gnipeek dna
,flesti thgin eht fo ssenkrad eht emoceb ydob s’renruoM was anaS yaw eht erutpac t’ndluoc
.erew yeht tahw yltcaxe ylekil saw
,renruoM desoporp
.hguoc t’ndluow tsehc sih tub
,spil sih kcams ot dnoces a rof ffo gniliart
,ihovatneL eht fo namahS etum ,anaS ,emit tsaL
.nworf peed a htiw worc ywodahs eht ta ecnalg ot mih gnisuac
,eb ot desu sgniht dias dah seirots ’srehcaet sih yaw eht ,lwob a otni deruop yltaen lla
.ot dias erew yeht ekil gnihton detca yeht tey dna
.ereh tuo eb t’ndluow uoy esiwrehto“
.oot ,uoy ni erif a evah uoY“
.detpurretni flow eht
erif eht fo elkcarc eht ylnO
.tluciffid eb ot demees ti tuB
gnileef egnarts taht llits saw ereht roF
.retnuH morf ssorca
.ebirt sih nihtiw noitisop sih fo syawaevig daed yna tuo kcip t’ndluoc eH
”,dnuora rehtag ot erif emoclew a gnikees ylerem erew ew spahreP“
.dereffo saw eh sdrow eht revo gniwehc llits ,nihc sih dehctarcs retto ehT ?ehs dluoc
.tsoh sa ,eud era uoy tfig eht uoy nevig tey ton evah I“
,stnemom wef a rof meht neewteb ria eht ni gnuh ecneliS
,ylwolS .deppots nehT
.dewob retto eht
.ereh teem ot esohc ew“
,thgin taht fo tser eht fo
”,nrobbuts si lesaew ehT“
,meht dnuora emit sih lla dneps ot smees“
.rennam elbatrofmoc tsom eht ni nosrep sih tuoba depparw
,niaga stseug sih ta dnuora decnalg anaS
,ereht ni gnivom ti leef dluoc eh dna
”.tes si ti mohw erofeb uoy si ti yhw nosaer a si ereht
,namahS ,wonk dluow flesruoy uoy“
,yllufthguoht anaS detseggus
”?namahS ,peels ot ecalp a uoy evaH
.efil siht ni ysae reve saw gnihtoN
rac' :dneherpmoc ot nigeb ton dluoc anaS sgniht fo deklat meht fo eerht eht sa
ecneserp raelc ehT
.ti nialpxe ot yaw tseb eht revo dellum eh sa ylwols gnikaeps ,retto eht nageb
edis sih ot llaf swap sih tel anaS ,hgis a htiW
,hturt eht gnillet saw retto ehT
,tirips-flow eht fo tsehc derruf kcalb eht no denoihsuc daeh sih dna
”.rehcaet on stpecca eh“
.regnif latnemirepxe na htiw
,kaeps ot ,yllatnemirepxe ,yltnatiseh
ytniatrecnu rof moor on saw erehT
seramthgin suoiriled fo sthgin eerht retfa taht dekramer ro
.drawrof evom ot woh deredisnoc ylluferac ,niaga ecno ,dna
.erif eht otni derats eh sa
…sevirra reve eh fi
”.eergasid dluow ohw esoht era erehT“ ”.su rof gnivil
,elkcuhc suovren a decrof namahs eht
dehgual flow eht tub
,gnilahxe saw rekaepS .htaerb mraw a
”?tonnac flesruoy yb uoy nehW
,etarepsed steg retnuh yrgnuh A
”,ti nrael reven uoy fi nevE“
... .shturt-flah dna yasraeh hcus no desab tnemegduj dessap yeht dibrof irutiÄ .ruomur dna pissog ot gninetsil
dessap dah sega retal ynam retfa hcihw
,selpoep eritne fo
kcab dna tnorf mih derevoc taht
,esingocer ton od I uoy dna ,ahavästeM dna
rebmemer dluoc eH
.sregnarts suoiretsym owt tem ereht dna
”?tirips nuS rieht evah rekdeH eht woh ekil
,deklat enirevlow eht dna flow ehT  2 fo 2 traP
yrots s’yadoT dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,noitnetta s’anaS dekrep tnemmoc ehT
gnaf eno htiw pil sih gnitib
,elbuort hguone desuac dah lesaew tahT .athonU ot
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
.wenk eh tahw htiw od ekam ot dah tub ,seman rof deksa evah dluow eh ,kaeps dluoc eh fI
.flow eht fo esoht ekil erom erew yeht fi ,oot srae sih dna
,retto eht edule dluow yromeM
.dne no dnats dna elgnit kcen sih no ruf eht edam
.stseug sih fo hcae ta gnicnalg
,ecalp siht hcaer ot raf dellevart I
,deunitnoc namahs eht
,sretnuh raluger ekil levart dluoc stirips taht
.noitasilaer suoivbo ylgnimees eht ta gninediw seye sih
owt sih fo noitnetta eht barg ot taorht sih gniraelc
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.tif ees ew sa ,sliart emag eht no ecalp ot ecalp morf evom ohw ,uoy ekilnu ton era ew ebyam tub“
,no tnew flow ehT
,nos—yltnerappa—sih ta erif eht hguorht dereep retnuH ”,ti si woH“
,neht rehto era uoY“
,lautir fo dnik emos rof fi sa denotni rekaepS
,spil sih ta ekop dna dorp ot deunitnoc anaS
.eciov s’flow eht fo enot ni egnahc eht yb denrecnoc ylthgils ,dehgis anaS
,tfel s’anaS no doots eh
,stirips erew yeht fI
,sreffo efil taht lla rof snraey dna gnuoy si eh“
snoitcnitxe dna 'nob-
renruoM ”,cillydi os era elpoep ruoy fo lla ton smees tI“
reve naht erom tlef eh yhw dna
,tseug driht ruo sekam taht esoppus I dnA“ .ylsuocuar
,stirips lufrewop fo ecneserp eht
,deirt eh retfa dnA
,laiceps t’nsaw erow eh gnihtolc ehT
.retteb nwonk evah dluohs eh tub ,rewsna laer a rof depoh d’eh ,niagA .rekaepS
,ecnahc yb ksat a nopu emoc uoy yenruoj ruoy ni nehw
,erusaert dedraoh dna
.riafnu demees hcihw
.ylthgils liocer retto eht edam tnemmoc ehT ”.nosaer a sah eh
ecaf sih revo swap sih deppuc anaS
,gnineve ni seert eht til llits tesnus ehT
.tfig tseug yna tsoh ruo dereffo“
”,sesroh eht seroda eH“
”,taht eveileb t’nod uoY“ .noitca ot athonU
,elpoep sih yb dettimmoc sgnorw dnem ot emoc d’eh nehw yllaicepsE
!ti dootsrednu yltnerappa d’yeht nevig ,noitseuq elbanosaer a saw tI
,meht leef tsomla dluoc eh litnu anaS otni derob seye s’enirevlow eht ”,si eh kniht I“
.gniht evila na ekil
.deggurhs rekaepS
.niaga nwod kcab gnilttes neht
”…ti rof drow ym ekat ton lliw uoy fI“
,gnitadimitni eb ot meht tnaem rekaepS eht rehtehW
.taes a koot yllanif dna
,nageb namahs ehT ”...wonk uoY“
.enoyreve rof tnuh eht liops nac retnuh etarepsed eno dna
.depoh dah eh sa noinummoc a ton
,tcepsorp eht deredisnoc anaS
”,yhw nosaer enO“ ”-yhw si tahT
.ereht tuo deniamer
,tis ton did worc ehT
.ten a fo eloh eht hguorht gnidils hsif llams a ekil
.worc eht sdrawot sdrow sih gnitcerid yldi
”,su erofeb gnigar erif eht ekil sI“ ”...athonU“
,retnuH yb dehtacs tlef anaS
.od uoy neve naht uoy tuoba erom wenk stseug ruoy nehw
,dennirg flow ehT
gnipmuj semalf eht
”?em morf seman eurt ruoy peek yhw
.anaS ot gniht ronim a hcus demees ti fi neve dna
.no sraew thgin eht won tuB“
dluow sevlesruoy sa lufrewop sa stirips taht delbmuh ma I dnA“
.dias anaS ”-uoy did tahW“
,dehsinif renruoM sa
”,ihovatneL eht fo namahs ,tämakriK fo nos ,anaS si eman sih ,kaeps tonnac eH“
.ssenlufekaw htiw dellif erom tlef reven d’eh tub
.renruoM dna retnuH dniheb gnidnats ,worc a eb ot mih delaever ecaf eht ylno taht os
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.erif eht morf yawa gnicaf won sih etipsed
yrots siht gnillet eb d’eh fi sa t’nsaw ti taht flesmih dengiser eh
,dennirg renruoM ”,tuB“ .dias retnuH
.emuser ot degilbo won saw eh ksat suoreno na erew saw eh tahw rof dezingocer
,seert eht hguorht dehsur dniw neddus A
.tnemetats suoiverp s’rekaepS ot thgiew gnidda
.ti tuoba od ot mih detnaw evah thgim renruoM eht tahw dna
.seert rif eht fo setteuohlis eht tsniaga ecnad meht gnihctaw
.selkcunk sih no daeh sih detser dna
demuserp ,nwonknU nigirO
,ria eht gnillif sdrib thgin fo eltsihw eht dna
.tsol ton s’eh wonk I woh s’tahT
rebma dna senob fo yrellewej lausu ehT
dettimda eb tsum ti hcihw
”,gnorts si rehto hcae rof tuo skool taht ebirt A“
?ot deen eh did ,neht tuB
.dennirg renruoM ”?spahrep ,rekaepS
,sgnitniaP evaC mlohsiauQ fo yevruS laitinI“
”.hsiw uoy fi ,retnuH em llac yam uoY
,giwt a htiw erif eht dekop flow eht
.laiceps gnihtyna sa seilppus gnirahs fo thguoht ihovatneL on
ydob sih fo seniltuo eht dna
,meht fo lla erofeb dehcterts llits htap eht
,mih ot dednah eb ot rewsna na rof degnol anaS
.thgin fo emit siht tuo raew ot emosrebmuc oot
.uoy ekil ,skao eht ekil
”.traeh ta ihovatneL eurt a s’eh wonk I woh s’tahT“
noitsuahxe ni seenk sih ot espalloc ot detnaw evah dluow eH
,rehtegot swap sih depsalc anaS ”.tsol
,lesaew degnahc a saw athonU
,retal sraey ,yrt dluow eH
,gnihtyna gnidih eb ot enadnum oot demees yeht hguohT
”!nos ruoy eb ton ot mialc nac ohw esoht era deedni wef suoicerp dna ,eyA“
nepo saw htuom sih dezilaer eH
stirips ot eud tcepser eht fo lufdnim ylpeed
,pil sih tib renruoM
pitregnif dna hsurb dna tnemgip
.lla retfa ,luos eht saw tnecs dnA
tuohs ot detnaw sdnah siH .elttil a ylno
”.namahS ,od ew tahw era eW
,semalf eht otni kcab kool ot denrut eh sa delbmum eh
,kcab dellup eh sa denediw seye s’anaS
.deklat ylpmis reven dna
”?neht ,od ew tahw fo rettam a si tI“
.noisulli na gnitaerc ta doog tsuj erew yeht spahrep
.anaS rof foorp hguone saw tahT
,enips s’retto eht pu llihc a tnes eciov dloc s’rekaepS
.thgis no meht detcepser dna dezingocer stirips dna lufrewop erom erew nemahs nehw
,retto eht revo denael eh dnA ”?lliw uoy fI
,dniw eht hguorht repsihw ebirt ruoy fo emoS“
.dias eh nehw ylprahs dekcalc kaeb s’rekaepS
.netsil ot ni denael lla dah yeht taht gniciton
”!enim ton ,nos ruoy s’eH“ .dias retnuH
ylpmis si ti ,ytilatipsoh ton si ti
,enirevlow eht ta detniop dna semit wef a tsehc sih depmub ylmrif eh
,niaga lufrovalf erew seirreb eht taht
elzzum sih deborP
deciton ebirt sih fo yna fI
mih ot derrucco reven tI
,elbmurg peed a htiw detsisni retnuH
?namahs a ot deneppah taht gniht fo tros eht taht ton saw rof
.meht htiw flesmih nrecnoc deen
.thgin tsal ereht neeb dah flesmih tub yna taht
,htaerb sih ni gnikcuS
kaolc s’rekaepS was
.stseug yranidro on erew eseht taht
.noitalever a hcus fo ekam ot tahw erus yleritne ton
?aes eht ot wolf revir eht seod woH“
edis eht ot daeh sih gnikcoc
,suoires dna dloc ,eciov rehtona ni tuc ”,siht sI“
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
.s’namahs eht morf sehcni saw ecaf sih llit
,denethgiarts erutsop s’enirevlow eht ”,ew llahS“
”-eh ,tsoh ruo teem ,emoc tuB .yldraH“
.evah ton did eh eugnot a detsiwt ti taht wen os llits hceeps fo noitasnes eht
,seirrebkcalb epir fo roloc eht
”,mih semusnoc ti erofeb ,erif taht lortnoc ot nrael tsum eH“
,enirevlow eht no ezag sih gniworran ,edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc retto ehT
tesnus fo sroloc eht lla dewolg llits ,ylegnarts dna
,ylesolc ton tub gnol rehtohcae nwonk dah ohw nemsebirt owt ekil
,wap eno no daeh sih gnitseR
.deifsitas yltnerappa ,evissapmi ecaf
.tsrif deneppah dah esoht fo hcihw
”cihtiloseM reppU
”?esir nus eht seod woH“
,dehgis enirevlow eht ”,yhw nosaer enO“
eb thgim siht ,sgnieb eseht gnoma ysetruoc eb thgim siht
,erehwesle si eh fI
retnuh yna llacer ton dluoc eh
,llet dluoc eh sa raf sa eurt saw tI
,tnagorra os eb dluoc stiripS
,edis eno ot dekcoc daeh
”.em dia ot ylerem raf os yenruoj
meht gnoma stirips gnorts fo
nos s’enirevlow a rof tnaem ti tahw detcepsus eh taht won mih fo tuo gnillaf saw hcamots s’anaS dna
”?em gniksa uoy erA“
.esufer ot esiwnu yrev
.nihtiw eugnot on saw erehT
.ruoivaheb s’lesaew eht rof esucxe na dnif ot detatiseh eh sa namahs eht ffo gnittuc
”,tey ereh lla ton er’eW“
,meht neewteb htrof dna kcab dekool anaS
.sezag esnetni htiw ruf sih otni nrub t’ndid yeht tsael ta
,erif eht fo edis s’anaS ot retnuH dniheb deppets dna
,taht dlot gnieb desiar lla erew eW“
’?em ssik ot gniyrt uoy era‘
,sesroh eht ot detoved erom neve dna
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.sselehtenon ,dias eh ”?woH“
,hguoc ot detnaw evah dluow eH
,smrof rieht fo owt desingocer ylno eh neht
.gninaem suonimo rieht revo dewehc eh sa
,tnemom a desuap rekaepS
”…ruoy emocrevo ot uoy sevird taht enO
,tniop siht ta niatrec saw sa
draeh eh gnihtemos saw siht spahreP
”.slatrommi eht dna daed eht morf egdelwonk gnikees
”,sesroh ehT“ ...saw ti
”!pleh t’nseod tahT“
.emit tsrif eht t’nsaw ti dna
”?mih wonk uoy taht“
,ecnanimod wohs ot tpmetta na sa ffo emac ti taht saw esac tsroW
kaolc dedooh a ni enoemos wohs ot hguone pu erif eht decar dna
.ti gnixif morf mih llats ot deraeppa dah sregnarts eseht won dna
s’namahS eht tem seye siH
,srats fo snrettap fo edam
,nosaer eno naht erom rof
,stnirptoof on erew erehT
,ta kool ot ,ngis on deedni ,srehtaef ro senob tnasaehp on
.rewsna sih tuoba niatrec yleritne ton
,ebirt sih ro tsitra sti fo gnihtyna wenk reven yeht hguoht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sduolc eht devom llits ezeerb eht
,niaga secnedicnioc eugav eht rof dehsiw tsomla retto eht fo traP
gnuoy eht evom ot demees ohw
?yawyna ,taht ekil gnihtemos dereffo neeb d’eh emit tsal eht saw nehw dnA
dooh sih derewol rekaepS
,ottorg enotsemil a fo llaw eht no derebmemer eh tahw fo gnihtemos tniap ot
.retto eht drawot ,ylprahs ,denrut daeh siH
,yawa dellup rekaepS
,flesti naht erom hcum gnihtemos naem thgim ssik a neht
namahs a ylno erehW .erehwemoS
loukaaR elbmeser ohw owt uoy ,oS“
hceeps fo rewop ehT
.stseug detcepxenu ,egnarts
…erew yeht detcepsus eh tahw erew elpoep eseht fi dnA
”,kle llat fo dreh a saw ti tbuod I tub
?retnuh rehto yna ekil secnaveirg rieht ria tsuj yeht t’ndluoc yhw
”cihtiloseM reppU demuserp ,nwonknU nigirO
.eciov sih denruter dah ohw
,srae s’anaS ni deregnil
?namahs a saw eh wonk sregnarts eseht did woh ,ti fo kniht ot emoC
worc eht revo gnikool ylluferac anaS
shtaed eht rof ,elbisnopser eb dluow ro ,elbisnopser saw ohw dna
denruter ereht sthguoht eht sa daeherof sih tsniaga smlap sih fo sleeh eht dnuorg ,denaorg dna
:detcepxe eh tahw ton tub
”.detcepxe eh naht erom hcum dnif llahs eh dna ,ecnalab eht thgir ot gnikees emoc sah eH“
.suoivbo t'nsaw depoh eh yaw a ni ,ylfeirb
,sbir sih no tsif sih gnicalP
,noitcudortni tuohtiw mih wenk yeht yhw
”,retfiL-tliK uoy llac ot thguo eh neht ,od ew tahw fo rettam a si ti fI“
.tes sah nus eht ecno ,peels sih mraw ot eerht ro owt htiw ,ediserif sih ta sgnoleb nam A
,regnif a desiar anaS ,ylwolS
.etulf a hguorht cisum ekil
,neht gnihtemos retfa erew uoY“
,athonU demat dah retnuh oN
.smra sih ni thgin eht dneps ot detnaw anaS rehtehw ksa t’ndid eH
won yad dna thgin sa raelc sa saw ti ,lla retfA
”?rof dellac saw I lesnuoc eht“
dehctarcs enirevlow ehT
,worc a eb ot
”,elpoep ruoy gnoma seman on evah eW
sdrow tsal esohT
,floWcaM boR dna xoFarakaS yb
.ewa ni worc eht ta dekool eH .reve sA
”,neht ecaep ruoy peeK“
,kaO eht fo neeb evah dluohs
,flesmih ta nwod decnalg retto ehT
.dias I sa si tI“ .worC eht ton
.ti pots ot enod eb dluoc gnihtyna rehtehw dna
,detressa renruoM
,thgif a rof desnet anaS .delworg retnuH
,worc eht ot denetsil eh sa hteet sih gnola bmuht sih gninnur
,tnemom a rof rethgirb wolg ot demees erif ehT ”.ylthgirb gninrub
,mih htaeneb evitroppus ro tfos ro mraw ssel on hguoht
,eticer dna hcaerp dna tnahc saw did eh lla fi sa
stirips eht dna ,reve sa
,suoires erom werg taht enot a ni deunitnoc
,edis eno ot daeh sih dekcoc ylwols rekaepS ”?ton yeht oD
,flesmih ot tsomla ,desum anaS
,maerd a neeb dah thgin elohw eht spahreP
.espmilg ot nekow d’eh gnihtemos saw siht spahreP
,pmac ta kcab erew
,sgnitniaP evaC mlohsiauQ fo yevruS laitinI“   yojne esaelP
,raf os llew gniog si tnemirepxe yrots evitaroballoc siht kniht ohw
,syaw dlo eht morf denrael uoy tuB .segnellahc“
gnieb fi sA .emit siht gnikaeps fo rennam sih ni etarebiled erom dna rewols ,retnuH derewsna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.sterces yna llet ot ylekilnu“
.emit tsrif eht rof eciov sih ni romuh fo ecart on htiw ,dias renruoM
,daor thgiarts gnol a fo dne raf eht ta retnuH was
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.erif dehsiugnitxe na yb enola saw eh ,ekow eh nehW
,desuma yldlim saw eciov s’flow ehT
.esolc oot ydaerla saw worc eht tub
.stseug sih fo hcae revo kool ot daeh sih denrut
,mih detpoda dah rebmem ebirt on
,sgnitniaP evaC mlohsiauQ fo yevruS laitinI“
,tsomerof lufetarg neeb evah dluohs eh desseug eH
.flesmih tub enoyna ot
.gnirewsna erofeb nihc sih ta ylevisnep
”,reisae hcum sriaffa eseht edam hceeps denigami syawla I“
”.devresbo era ew dna“
,mih gnitroppus dna dnuora depparw smra gnorts
?nur ot nrael esroh eht seod woH
,yltcaf fo rettam os ekops tsuj yeht fi ro
.ylimaf nwo sih dluow eh ekil
,ydob sih gnillif sseniraew lufssilb
,detcejretni worc eht ”,eb yam eW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.mih ot gnulc llits
”,eert a rednu elbatrofmoc flesym ekam nac I“
.niaga ecno pu ekops retto eht litnu
?mih hcaer ot elba eb lliw irutiÄ dna irosaR“ ,yromem sih hguorht sregnif gninnur fi sa
,retto eht delbmum
namahs retto eht
?detnaw yeht lesaew eht ti saw ,neht oS
?rettam ti did tahw dnA .t’ndluow eh
”.kaeps sa llew sa ,netsil I“
sesnes sih gnola deyalp taht
.maerd a otni evow dna gnipeels elihw
.semoc nwad erofeb yas tsum ew ,rehtona eno ot yas dluow ew tahW
”.ylisae os enoemos no pu evig t’ndluow
”.ytilatipsoh s’elpoep ruoy rof esiarp ylno draeh evah I ,ereh em teg ot nekat evah I yenruoj eht no ,lla retfA“
”.emit tsrif eht eb ton dluow tI“ ,dias anaS
.daeh s’anaS ni dekcilc ti nehw s’tahT
”?eveileb yllaer uoy tahw taht sI“
.ytinrete dna emit yb nettogrof dna dniheb tfel esiwekil erew sevlesmeht yeht erofeb
.tol a tnaem ylerus tirips a morf tnemilpmoc a rof
”.enod era ew nehw levart ot raf evah lliw I dna
,mrotsrednuht tnatsid a fo llems eht ekil sgnul sih otni desserp dna htuom dna eson sih dellif ti dna ,yllufecrof ,ylidaets
,ylluferac denetsil eh sa desiar worbeye na
,no gniog saw tahw uoy llet dluoc eh fi nevE