,seirellag rieht dna srohtua eht ot sknil htiw decnuonna era sedosipe wen erehw
,41 nettirw dna sedosipe 21 dedrocer s'ohw
ecnuonna ot yppah yrev m'I oS
,tnuocca rettiwT laiciffo s'tsacdop eht detrats yltnecer s'eh dnA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT .deepsdog
.eugolatac kcab eht morf sedosipe citnamor emos detaruc yltnecer dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
seirots fo seires goD fo tsohG eht decudorp eh ,neewollaH tsaL
.tsacdop eht no ereh uoy rof seirots daer ev'ohw srelletyrots rehto yb denioj neeb ev'I
.stnemecnuonna rehto emos ebyam ,swonk ohw dna
.draoba boR evah ot dalg m'I
.uoy htiw tnemecnuonna na erahs ot desaelp m'I
,ecalperif eht fo dneirf rehtona htiw noitaroballoc a gnidulcni
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m'I
.keew txen gnitrats sedosipe gnicudortni dna ,gnitide ,gnicudorp
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR eman eht rebmemer yam uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT fo tsoh-oc sa em gninioj eb lliw
,floWcaM boR taht
,dopgodfoeciov@
tsacdop eht fo ylla hcnuats a neeb s'eH
mih gnihsiw ni em nioj ll'uoy epoh I dna
,wohs eht ot gnirb ll'eh saedi hserf tahw ees ot deticxe m'I
,rekihhctih flowerew
.dellac era inmula s'tsacdop ruo sa
,gnitceles htiw pleh ll'eH
.ti dnuora pu gnarps taht sretirw fo ytinummoc eht ot dneirf layol a dna
,raey tsal eht revO