.devlovni eb thgim ecnamor esuaceb tsuj ti did efiw eht taht noisulcnoc eht ot pmuj t’ndluohs—esle enoemos neeb ev’dluoc ti sseug I
",em gnirehtob neeb s'taht noitseuq eht deksa uoy fo rehtieN"
deredro d’yeht ecnO
.tnaromroc eht dias
,desop saw ydob eht dna ,roolf pot eht no saw eciffo ehT !ylsuoivbo
,nehctik s’amdnarG ot kcab em koot
taht thgir etiuq er’uoy ,woN"
”.evil ot gnol evah ton seod eh dlot eb ot
.taorht a tuc ot eno ylno
,enola hguone llew tfel evah dluohs I wonk I dnA
,ytilibisnopser gnimialc repap eht ot rettel a dnes ton yhw neht
,elbat eht otno ti pals mih draeh I tub—
.ehcatsum sih fo shtped eht ni dehpmurrah gats eht
,taehc a ekil leef I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
tnaromroc eht rof regal a dna igoreip egasuas
llew‘“ moor eht ni esle enoyna naht rewol evatco na tsael ta gnikaeps mih tfel llits hcihw ,noitatimi ni yltnerappa ,pu eciov sih dehctip eh
.neht ,ylprahs em ta pu dekool eH
,netsil ot enoemos detnaw ohw namdam detartsurf a tsuj saw ti"
.rellik eno naht erom
,lleW :dias I tey dna
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,troffe sekat esreV
!tcartnoc eht dengis ohw retsinim tenibac eht emoc tsum txen tub ,su enod
.lla retfa teop a era uoy
'?sriatspu naM eht'
dedorroC‘ ?tsaehtron deifitrof eht no yrellitra detadpu revo nevaeh ot gniyrc neeb lla sepyt htuomduol gnuoy tnelodni eht t’nevah—
,kniht nam a sekam tI“
gninetsil rof yaw niatrec a gnittis neeb dah eh fi sa
.tonnac yllausu I taht timda ot dah I
.egassem lativ emos sah eh"
spahrep ,noissesbo suoigiler esnetni na oS
.meht etaicerppa lliw cilbup eht tbuod on evah I
’ropav sa edaf ylerem lliw sevil
,krof sih fo eldnah eht htiw gats eht drawot derutseg erah ehT
”,yhw wonk uoy kniht uoY“
”.rehtie ti ees t’nod I esuaceb
,yrteop gnitirw tpek daetsni evah oT
,niaga snier lanoitasrevnoc eht barg dna meht fo daeha teg ot sdrow reh hsur ot dah tnaromroc eht "…naem I ,on oN"
nimda na osla si dna
esuaceb ,ereht eb ot ti esohc enoemos esuaceb ereht si gnihtyrevE
”.yalp d’yeht drocer eht ot dnA
,noitanalpxe eht ,meop eht erus gnikam saw gnillik eht fo trap eroferehT
.egnyraLeD .rM tuoba thguoht I dnA
.reward ksed sih morf ,segap eht neewteb deffuts repap parcs fo seceip htiw ,koobeton kciht a dellup eh
,tuoba eb ot thguo meop a kniht uoy revetahw ,kooL
sevitarepmi era segru nwo s’eno taht noisuled eht dnA
.taht ta pu tas eH
.ehcatsum dexaw yhsub a dna sehtolc esicerp ,prahs erow gats ehT
?redrum devlosnu ,gnikcohs a fo mitciv eht yb smeop tuB
”,dneirf ym ,gnorw ylbahgual
”detaicerppA si kroW s'enO wonK ot trofmoC taerG a si tI“ saw sihT
,sgnilbmar cainam ro
.serac ylurt eno-on teY
,gnitagitsevni trats d’I erehw s’taht ,llew“
tahW" "?meop a ti si yhW"
'eh' lacitehtopyh ruoy—gnillik eht deerced rehtona syas meop eht ,tnarg lliw I
!snopaew eht esu ll’ohw lareneg ehT
.railimaf dednuos taht ti tuoba gnihtemos saw ereht
dluoW .krow ym ot gniees fo daetsnI
,ytic taerg a fo serusaelp tsefeihc eht fo eno si noitasrevnoc draehrevo eht tub
”!tnemnrevog a nwod sgnirb taht sisirc fo dnik eht emoceb ot laitnetop eht sah sihT“
,od ot evol dluow revir eht ssorca raseac dneterp taht tahw wonk lla eW“
sehctam ti fi oS
,erah eht rof eciuj elppaenip dna yeksihw dna ehciuq noino
.ni emac uoy nehw tcejbus taht no gnihtemos fo gnidrow eht htiw gniyot saw I“
,sretsinac sag eht eb dluow ’sllehs
.ereh ma I taht won ,elbativeni si gniyd eht diarfa m’I ,dias I ,ris lleW
.skaerb swen eht nehw etiteppa cilbup eht tehw oT
,dehsinif tnaromroc ehT
”.neht ,krow ot kcaB“
.ereht tseretni on
".htaed s’egnyraLeD .M rof ton fi taht gniod eb t'ndluow eW
woble ym dniheb tsuj elbat eht ot yaw sih deredluohs ohw gats eht dias
”?noitaterpretni rehto emos ees uoY“
"?neht ,rellik eno saw siht kniht uoY"
,dezigolopa I ”.uoy derih
.derongi eb tonnac ti taht
ton noitaterpretni ruoy erew nevE“
.tcerroc oot lla rotcepsni yhtrow eht kniht I ereht"
,gniddew rieht ta ti ot decnad stnerapdnarg yM
”.enod stnaw ehs tahw gniksa neve tuohtiw
kniht thgim eh naht netfo erom tub
.denoitnem uoy noitidnoc traeh eht si ereht ,ton I erew neve dnA
.ydnarb ym dehsinif I
.elihw a rof tsael ta ,esle gnihton fo eb lliw sefac eht ni klat ehT
.erom ecno htrof dleh gats eht—
.dneirf ym ,ecneitaP"
.s’erah eht naht yroeht siht redisnoc ot deraperp erom saw gats eht ekil dednuos tI
.denialpxe ehs ”,syas ti tahw t’nsi taht tub ’,tlips si doolb‘ dias uoY“ ”?tahW“
,revewoh ,debrutsid saw noitcepsortni liuqnart yM
— swen eht dehsalf ereht ,seuh gnihceercs nI
,llew‘ ,yas ot hguone denedlobme era stsihcrana deniarb-noom emos fi
!ylsuoivbo ,redrum rehtonA“
!siht ekil ton tsael ,sredrum rieht ot noitnetta ward t’nod yeht ,sboM !nees saw
”!ylsuoires ti gnikat era eW“
;puorg margeleT erutaretiL edisdliW eht rof
.pu peek ot elba eb t’now sllatskoob eht ,ris yhW
.dnim sih nworhtrevo sah ti taht ylgnorts oS
.sey ,cainam detartsurf A"
,os erew taht fi tuB
,t’ndid ti yas dluoc meht fo rehtien os yletaidemmi deunitnoc neht ,dehsinif eh
’sU‘ !dnammoc fo niahc a
,thgim hcihw fo enO
nezod a era erehT
.ssertsim ro efiw rehto emos
regnarts etelpmoc a llik ot ylekil nosrep fo tros eht dluow ,os fI .seY
.gninialpxe rof yaw tnereffid a tis ot dah won dna
,owt ro rehsilbup evitcepsorp a fo seciffo tuo kees ot dedeen I
.ekaw sih ni deliart taht tnaromroc eht dna erah eht ot
,derutnev tnaromroc eht ",neht ,kniht uoY"
’sevil ruo‘ dna
’!nalp eht devorppa ohw tnediserp ehT
,dallab citnamor dlo yppas a
.enola t’nsaw eh dezilaer eh nehw dias dah daot dlo eht gniht tsrif eht saw
lliK' ?sesserpxe ti taht ehcysp fo dnik eht sserpxe ot deen oT ?meop siht
,rellik eht ot ,gniht tnatropmi eht taht demussa ev'uoy tuB
-wonk tsum flesmih sa hcus namssenisub elbatcepser A
’!sniamer tfel gnihton‘ dna ’,ropav sa edaf lliw sevil ruo‘ ’,serac ylurt eno-on‘ :egassem a tahw dna
eht era meht fo owt eht fi
.tnaromroc eht detcejretni ”’,tlipS‘ toN
etarebiled a gnivaeL
”!eno eht tsuj wonk I !deedni ho ,hO“
.os saw taht ecneirepxe ym ni ,sey taht mih dlot I
,redisnoc ot deppots gats eht ”,hO“
ti setirw enoemos fi
”!lliw I ,uoy knahT“
;sniamer tfel gnihton nehW
!ti syas ti ,ti yas t’nod I“
”?taht draeh reve uoy fo rehtiE“
.egaW namuH ehT" :daer neht dna
,yobloohcs deticxe na ekil dekool eH
.tfel d’yeht ecno ydnarb rehtona deredro I
.siht gniyojne saw erah ehT ".dneirf
”!dloc nur doolb ruoy ekam t’nseod taht em llet woN“  ".sniev
”?emussa I“ ,dias erah eht
?stelhpmap tuo evael ro ,draob eciton a pu gnah ro
.hgis detnioppasid a sa tuo emac ti tub
,etirovaf a tceles dluoc uoy ,ris ,spahreP
?egnyraLeD emM a ereht si
?ssenisub ylimaf eht nur ot deerga reven dah yeht hsiw elpoep od
si yrots s’yadoT dna
ti ecalp t’ndluoc I
’eh‘ ,redrum s’egnyraLeD .rM redro tsuj t’ndid ’eh‘ esuaceB !bom a ton ,oN“ ”.sisirc latnemnrevog a yldrah tub ,nrecnoc a er’yeht“
,sgnillik ruo fo semoc tahw si epoh ,si tahT
,etarebiled saw meop eht gnidloh ydob eht fo noitisop eht
.egnyraLeD sa ega emas eht tuoba erew yeht dna
teerts llennoD’O .tS tfel I sa gnittes saw nus ehT
ytrap rehto emos morf
,tseuqer a defashcuov erew I fI“
slleH derehtiw ni sllehs gnidorroC
sriats eht pu em peews dnA
yaw a ni egassem eht tneserp tsum eH
”.wonk eW .dneirf ym ,os su dlot uoy nehT“
,redrum siht si sriatspu nam eht llik ot repap fo pils A“
ekas eht rof si redrum eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
"?erew ydaerla ew deciton t'ndah uoY"
,floWcaM boR yb dna
”?sseug a evah uoY“
,detrons eh ”,enil tsal tahT
,neht ti hguorht su klaw“
,yhw ,siht htiw yawa teg yeht fI
,detrons eh ”,em ta kooL“
’eH‘ taht gnizilaer elttiL
gnihtemos llits s’ti
'.serac ylurt eno-on' ,sala ,tuB
,srotanes suoiruf gnoma ecnelis rof gnillac saw ehs ekil sgniw reh pu dleh tnaromroc eht ”!thgirllA“ ”!uoy nmad
?yas ot tnatropmi gnihtemos evah yeht leef niaga yeht erofeb gnol woh
.enog gnol erew sevitceted ehT
.seye s’daot eht ni maelg tnemeticxe was I
,otsefinam a tsuj erew ti fi"
.tekcop renni ym ni smeop fo tpircsunam eht
”!noisavni dna ,soahC
ot gnihtemos naem dluow ti thguoht yeht
.sehtolc nialp eht htiw derehtob evah ton llew sa thgim yeht taht ecilop sehtolcnialp ylraelc os erew yehT
”.ris ,nissassa yranidroartxe na era uoY“
”!gnihton segnahc ti taht emas eht ot hguone esolc snaem taht ,lleW “
!skrowyrdnuoF egnyraLeD
.erah eht deffins
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,redrum eht fo ekas eht rof ton si egassem eht ,oN
,mih gnippots on saw ereht mutnemom hguone pu tliub dah erah eht
,eciffo eht ni tuo ti daer uoy nehw ,lleW“
.uoy llet em tel ,gninrom ysub a dah d’I
,noonretfa na fo ,teerts llennoD'O .tS no nwod ,s’seuqcaJ ykcuL ni saw I  floWcaM boR dna xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb
,dedeeccus eh tsenoh eb ot dnA
.yrtsudni sseldog htiw ti decalper ,ytitcnas si sleef eh tahw denodnaba sah yteicos taht yteixna
"?ti fo dne eht s’taht dna
a ekam ot saw htaed siht snaem eulc suoivbo dna
’eH‘ .ksed eht no doolb eht fo tuo
miH llac ot esnes ekam ton ti dluow dna
.repap fo pils eht meht evag
"?yrteop fo noitinifed eht dna yroeht yraretil ssucsid ot tuoba yllaer ew erA" .ypmurg llits saw gats ehT "?naem uoy od
’eH‘ taht skniht rellik eht suht ,nommocnu ton si
”.taht ta ,eno siht llifluf dluoc uoy woh ees ton od I ,lleW .hA“
.gnieelf ro gnithgif
”?stseuqer tsal ekat uoy oD“
,denori taochcnert sih erow eH
'naM' taht eciton uoY .elpmaxe rof 'sriatspu naM eht
ssertsim a ro efiw a esuaceb eb thgim taht
”-neht ,lla retfa stsihcrana fo yteicos terces a si siht fi tuB
.taoc sih no dellup erah ehT
”.sregnarts fo shtaed eht ffo gnivil a gnikam ni enola ton era uoy taht
.sevlesmeht ysub eb llits dluow srettesepyt dna srotide eht lla
”’sniev morf tilps
yawa denrut ecaf ym tpek I
,flesmih ot elkcuhc ot deirt eH
.edistuo teerts eht morf ni deirrac tnemugra na yb
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR dna
,gats eht rof hciwdnas dna eeffoc—
.rof saw ti reveohw
”.deirt evah I em eveileB .ris ,yrteop hsilbup ot stnaw ydoboN
”detaicerppA si kroW s'enO wonK ot trofmoC taerG a si tI“
,egassem a dnes ot ,tniop
",sleef wollef a oS" "!flesmih si
.egassem a erofereht si ti tahT
”.regal eht dellems I litnu
?ti evah uoy fi suonimo dna
.repap fo pils siht evag
,snoitnem meop eht ’ruo‘ eht dna ’su‘
.nehw tub ,niaga ekirts lliw yeht fi fo noitseuq a ton si tI
.yad eht ni kcab ,selpuoc rof ralupop yrev saw tI“
,gnihton tsoc taht esoht gnoma tsael ta
”!ymra eht rof snopaew erutcafunam ot detcartnoC
.renroc eht ni taes eht koot erah ehT
!meht eunitnoc ot naem ew os
.tnemom yna ta edagirb a nioj ot pu dellac eb thgim eh fi sa esicerp dna trohs tuc sreltna sih dna
,eb dluow kcehc d’I gniht tsrif eht ,lleW“
.deunitnoc tnaromroc eht ,ylper on tog yltnerappa ehs nehW
”.hcaer a eb llits dluow taht“
:llew sa gnineve ysub a eb ot dekool tI
.em dniheb dessap yeht sa
.detnaw eh tahw si taht fi
.tniop a dah ohw ,gats eht delworg
tuoba tuo dnuof
emussa tey ton deen ew ,yldnoceS"
ssenisub nwo ym dna knird ym gnidnim fo esneterp lla gninodnaba tuohtiw ton—taoc sih morf dellup eh tahw ees t’ndluoc I
epoh‘ ,lla fo gninmad tsoM
,daeh sih koohs erah eht ”,suoredrum woh rettam on ,stneduts tnedissid emos ,esac yna nI“
:desserp I os ,mih edausrep ot tsomla demees taht dnA
'.mirg' naht rehtar 'gnitanicsaf' yas ot detnaw ylraelc eh hguoht ,erah eht dehsinif ",tcepsorp mirg A
,meop a etirw ot dnah eno ylno sekat tI
.elbat nehctik eht no krowemoh ym did I elihw noonretfa eht ni reeb fo ssalg a gnivah apmarG ot
”!tnemnrevog nellaf a ot pu dda t’nod“
?ereht od uoy dluoc tahw
,neht ,ecneirepxe ruoy nI“
.ydnarb dedeen hcum a gnivah
wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,ronoh reh egneva ot ,flaheb s’namow a si kniht yeht tahw no tca ot elpoep rof fo draehnu t’nsI
.sniev morf tilps si epoh erehW
,ropav sa edaf ylerem lliw sevil ruO
xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb
”,norab rebbor gniregnomraw a dellik ew
’,gnos rieht‘ saw taht fI
,ytic eht revo ,swodniw eht tuo ylluftsiw dekool eH
,noitazinagro seilpmI .sredro s’ydobemos no saw redrum siht snaem hcihw ,meop siht .e.i ’repap fo pils‘ siht ’su‘ evag
repat rehtona thgil gnilrad yM“
,sraey tsal eseht dlos dna edam evah I tahw nevig ,esoppus I dnA“
,taes sih ni detfihs dna taorht sih deraelc erah ehT ".os etiuQ"
".drow rieht ta nekat eb ot ton era sreredrum dna
",ti htiw no teG" ".egassem eht fo
fo daetsni ,uoy htiw tahc dna tis tsuj I taht citehtapa dna dlo os“
.tey tsuj eb ot erehwyna dah I fi sa t’nsaw ti dna
”?sdrow tsal ym raeh ot ereht si esle ohw ,neht tuB
”?sbom eht fo eno saw ti oS“
”.dnatsrednu etiuq I .esruoc fo ,hA“
.ssalg ytpme reh otni derats tnaromroc eht
”.ekas s’noitnetta rof tsuj gniyd
.elpoep cificeps ot ,nosrep cificeps a yb nettirw
?ti raeh tsael ta I thgiM
,hguone thgir eb d’uoy ,yddud ydduf dlo hcir emos yb smeop emos ylno s’ti fi
.seitilibapac ym dnoyeb era tros taht fo sgniht tsoM
,evael ot mohw htiw rehsilbup a rof gnikool tnew dna
,pordsevae ot edur si ti wonk I ,sey dnA
,thginrevo ,ylsuomynona
,rettib a ekil sdnuos tahw gnikam neht
.ytilaitnedifnoc tneilc fo rettam a saw ti
,neht tuB .smeop ym daer elpoep taht eb dluow ti
,yltneg ,dias erah eht
,eeffoc sih deplug gats eht
,mih derussa I ,smret esoht ni yltcaxe ton spahreP
”.gnorw tsuj er’uoY“
.erac meht ekam tsum eH
”.ni deveileb yllautca I gnihtemos rof derebmemer eb dluoc dna
,esiwegde ni drow a tog yllanif tnaromroc eht
"?ti fo dne eht tuB
.retiaw a rof delangis ehs sa tnaromroc eht detsisni
”.ot ti tnaem retirw eht neht
?swollof tahw neht dna ,sdeen eh ytinutroppo eht tsuJ
.hguoht ’,tilpS‘ ,syas tI“
.ragus ro klim fo kcal gnikcohs eht rof ylsuonimo erom neve
,sehcnul rieht rof diap dna ssertiaw eht nwod deggalf erah eht sa gats eht delbmurg ”,esnes sekaM“ ”.yawyna
derehtiw' ,esrev dnoces eht si hcihw fo tluser ehT
.yadiloh a nevig gnieb s’eh eveileb tey ton seod ohw
.ti dnif ot tnaem era ew taht dna
?ssenisub s’egnyraLeD .rM etal eht saw tahw dnA
”.erahs ot I dna uoy roF ,yag dna riaf os ,yawaedih a oT
,yllaretil nekat eb ot ton era smeop tub—
.ti tuoba gniklat ,era ew ereh rof
:ylrae oot llits saw ti tub
ti od ot syaw renaelc dna refas
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
”?yhtrow dna lufituaeb gnihtemos ecudorp yllanif
"?ti saw tahw oS .nosaer a rof os od yeht
.nac uoy sa riaffa elbadiovanu eht fo tuo hcum sa teg llew sa yam uoY
.detaicerppa si krow s’eno wonk ot trofmoc taerg a si tI
etirw ot ylekil eb osla
tahT“ .ssalg reh detfil tnaromroc ehT
,dias I ,ris ,ees uoY
.rettel latipac eht niaga ':slleH
”!meop a no desab siht yas uoY“
”detaicerppA si kroW s'enO wonK ot trofmoC taerG a si tI“   yojne esaelP
”!lla si ,ylsuoires siht gnikat era uoy fo rehtien taht em seirroW“
citpyrc gnihtemos
.delims I ,ris ,uoy knahT
',doG' sezilatipac eno yaw emas eht ,dezilatipac si
,ti fo ydorap gniriapsed ,yrgna
?nosrep eno yb enod eb siht dluoC"
”!rellik elos a ton ,puorg a ylpmi
!htnom tsal gnitset rof decnuonna
ruo‘ :esrev dnoces eht ta kooL
si doolb‘ syas tI“
’repap fo pils‘ siht dloh ot ,metrom-tsop
.kceps a naht erom eb ot nosrep rehto yna rof hgih oot weiv a
?hguoht ,didros dna ,paehc …mees ton ti seoD“
,eulc a s’tI
,ygolohcysp fo noitcelfer a ro tnemetats lacitilop a s’ti rehtehw
"emulP eht morF" deltit noitcelloc yrteop tsrif sih hsilbup-fles ot noos si ohw ,xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb
”,traeh dab a evah I yas srotcod ehT“
.yrruFoS no gnitirw sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb gnuoY saW dlroW eht nehW ni dehsilbup yltnecer
.yna sa gnikool trats ot ecalp a doog sa s’ti dna“
”?tahw ot taerht A“ ”!taerht a si“
.esrev ni eb ot ti rof deen on s'ereht neht
”!od yeht rewop ngierof a yb detcerid dna dednuf er’yeht fI“
’!sniev morf tlips si
.deilper erah eht
sah ohw yas nac uoy enigami t’nod I“
,rehtegotla ssenisub dehcterw eht nodnaba ot flesym thguorb evah dluoc I taht
;sriatspu naM eht llik oT repap fo pils a su nevig s'eH
?yretsym eht evlos ot seulc eht niatnoc ylterces ,swonk ohw
.ti nialpxe ot ylerem si egassem eht dna redrum eht si
.desuma ,detpurretni erah eht
.tseretni ot ytisoiruc ym denrut hcihW
,teop doog a sevlesmeht llac yllautca dluoc yeht litnu lliks niag