.raeb eht ta dekool eilrahC
”,yug gib ,thgir erew uoy ekil skooL“
”?huh ,ni stauqs emos teg s’tel ,no emoC“ .dias eh
?thgir ,sporp fo xob gib siht gnidloh ereht m’I neht oS“
”?netfo ecalp siht ot emoc uoy ,oS“
.eilrahC dias ”!eniaM ,hoO“
,eromyna wodahs reh rednu ton er’uoy taht si yas nac I tahw tuB
:nem ot detcartta saw seluJ
.daehtsaM eilrahC si siht ,nailuJ“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.snoitnetta s’anut eht yb derettalf ylegnarts tlef eh ,gnihtyna fi
:ti no etanimur ot gnol mih ekat ton did tI
.nailuJ ot txen hcneb eht no tas neht dna ,llaw rekcol eht ffo dehsup eH
,noos oiduts nrop a gnitrats fo gnikniht erew sevY yddub sih dna eh ,naem I“
nosrep reeuq a elihw
”.ereh em gnignirb roF .uoy knahT …I“
.ylthgils gnihctiwt dnah sih ,dewollaws eh
.tahw ro ,yag m’I fi wonk neve t’nod I …I“
,yawa enog hcum ytterp dah elims ykcoc taht dna ,dexaler erom dekool erutsop siH
sa sdneirflrig-xe sih fo yna ot derrefer reven dah eh dezilaer nailuJ taht dnoces a retfa saw tI
.ylthgil ti debbad recreip eht sa
taht tug dnuor ylthgils a evoba tuo dettuj taht tsehc ekil-lerrab eht revo
.anut eht sdrawot ezag sih gninrut ,deknilb nailuJ
.ti ta yltcerid kool dluoc eh os nwod ecaf s’raeb eht elgna ot pu ti gnignirb ,’seluJ morf dnah sih depsalcnu eH
”.ydaer gnitteg er’uoy taht ereh steg eh nehw wonk rettops ruoy
”.ereht teg ot srewohs eht ssap ot evah uoy esuaceb ti tih uoy nehw wonk ll’uoy dna ,kcab eht ni yaw taht rof aera rekcol etarapes a s’erehT
,rehtaf dna rehtom sih neewteb deneppah tahw dessucsid netfo ton dah eH
”.llehs ruoy fo tuo uoy gnikaerb fo trap eb ot teg I dalg m’I ,lleW“ .dias ehs
,elims fo dnik erar yrev
”.evah yeht melborp ylno eht t’nera secitcarp ytefas elbanoitseuq ,ton naht ylekil eroM“
.seluJ dias ”…eilrahC ,yaS“
…tpek I taht si wonk I llA
”.rehtie tsal eht eb t’now uoy dna ,gnicreip a fo suovren neeb reve s’ohw yug gib tsrif eht ton er’uoY
.hcneb eht ssorca seye eulb-yks esoht ot dna
”?thginot ereht eb ll’eh dnA .ees I“
,ttub lufituaeb taht
,eman sih fo mrof denetrohs a hcus yb mih ot refer enoyna draeh reven d’eH
,rorrim eht ni dekool ecaf sih yaw eht htiw deifsitas yletelpmoc tlef eh
.redluohs sih revo eralg s’rehtom sih fo thgiew eht gnileef ,mih dniheb ecnalg ylsuoicsnocbus nailuJ edam pets llams siht neve tuB
.ylthgit oot spahrep ,pu dnuow dekool
worbeye thgir sih evoba gnits thgil a tlef eh retfa noos dna ,seye sih desolc seluJ
,yrev a flesmih dewolla seluJ dna
”.…os ,rehtaew toh ot desu tog reven I tub ,elihw a ni rehtaew redloc ni neeb t’nevah I“ .deddon nailuJ
”.yllautneve ni thgir tif ll’uoy ,yfmoc tlef I erofeb ereh ’nieb fo htnom a tuoba koot ti wonk I
.dias eh ”,enif s’ti ,on-
”.tnemtrapa taht revo lla em htiw yaw sih dah eh dna ecalp sih ot kcab em koot eh erofeb ruoh flah a ereht deyats neve ylerab eW
”,siht ekil flesym erolpxe ot ereh gnivom saw I taht rehtom ym llet neve t’ndid …I“
”.ecalp gnitrats a tog ev’ew neht ,dooG“ ”…os kniht I“
ohw fo hturt eht ezilaer tsrif yam nosrep a syaw elbissop eht lla rof ,dezirogetac ro
”?suovren syawla stneilc erA“
”.etal gninnur eb ot smees eh tub
.ruoh na rof mih gniwonk ylno retfa neve ,mih hguorht thgir nees dah eilrahC ekil tlef eh ,yaw egnarts a nI
hcihw ,luftsul gnihtyna fo naht noitarimda fo eno erom saw kool s’tar eht llet dluoc eh tub ,esruoc fo ,ti fo erawa saw nailuJ
”?taht tuoba thgir I mA
.ydob s’nailuJ degguh pot knat eht yaw eht dleheb eh sa gnilims ,nwod dekool eH .dias eh
.roolf eht ot decnalg neht eH
.desuap nailuJ ,ereh dnA
:yrevocsid fo tnemom emos evah
,daeh sih ni dnuora ecnuob ti tel eh sa tuB
”,yentruoC ,em rettalf uoY“
.myg eht revo lla sllaw eht ffo gnuh taht sgalf edirP fo rebmun eht osla saw ti
.gnittahc ,edis eht ot ffo gnidnats wehttaM was nailuJ
.teerts eht ffo tem dah eh regnarts yna ot ssel hcum
.daeh sih ni dnuora eman eht gnissot
”.erom meht od ot ekil dluow I dnA“
”.dnuora uoy wohs ot tiaw t’nac I“
.seohs sih otni teef sih gnillup dna pu gnidnats ,delims suht eH
”.ti ot desu ton llits m’I“
,ereh tuo yaw eht lla evom ot erised sih fo draeh dah ehs ecnis revE
.kcab delims eilrahC
”?thgir ,worb thgir ehT“
.egnar ecirp ym fo tuo tib a s’ti yllausU“
.eilrahC ot dekool neht eH .dias eh
”.yawa elim a morf sevlesmeht gnirevocsid llits era taht sepyt eht tops ot nrael uoy
”.ffuts namgnorts ni detseretni yllautca enoemos ees uoy netfo ton s’tI
,evohs eno htiw ,neht dnA
.deilper seluJ ”,oga sraey owt
,mih depolevne taht trofmoc fo gnileef siht
.sdapwap sih tsniaga selacs hsif fo noitasnes elbarusaelp
”,eciton trohs no sgnicreip seod ohw dneirf a evah I tub—
”,eurT“ .dettimda eh
”,ti rof kool ot erehw wonk uoy dna em er’uoy nehw ,si tI“ .deksa nailuJ
,dexaler yltnatsni selcsum sih tub ,tnemom taht ta mih revo emac tahw wonk ton did eH
”tnemoM A sekaT ylnO tI“
.tuo worb sih xaoc ot tsuj
,no gniog erom gnihtemos saw ereht ebyaM
.loop detanirolhc a ekil sllems ti dna ,lacisnesnon dna dab syawla si ciffart eht ,ysub repus s’tI
”?ti t’nseod ,raey fo emit siht rof deveels-trohs tib a smees tahT“
.peed dna gnilbmur eciov sih ,dias anut eht
”?erudecorp dradnatS“
.nwod gnikool ,delahxe eH
.ti dnuora ezeeuqs dna dnah sih ekat dnah delacs a tlef eH
.detcepxe naht repeed tnew ti ekil dekool ti dna ,senihcam fo stol
redaorb saw elims s’anut siht taht tpecxe ,erom hcum oot gnihtyna
”,gnortsmrA .rM ,era uoy suovren woh desirprus erom m’I ,yltsenoH“
.seluJ ta ylduol gnilkcuhc ,dehgual eilrahC
.dias eh ”,ocsicnarF naS ot emoclew ,seluJ ,lleW“
tel ll’I“ .wehttaM dias ”,thgirlA“
.llab nottoc a dna elttob a gnibbarg erofeb ,delahxe neht ehS
”?myg suoiverp a morf nemiger gniniart a evah uoY“ .delahxe eH
”.taht htiw pleh ot sdneirf emos ksa nac I tub
.deilper seluJ ”,seY“
”.taht no em tsurT“
”.spmoc namgnorts gniod detrats I ecnis ,elihw a rof ti tuoba thguoht
.yllufituaeb rehtar erugif sih detnemilpmoc oottat eht dna ,selcsum ecin dah llits anut eht
:recreip sih ot denrut neht seluJ
”.eno ni doog kool d’I kniht I
.nettog dah yeht esolc woh ot noitnetta diap yllaer yeht dah ron ,dnim on ti diap dah ffats tnaruatser ehT
;dah ydaerla d’eh naht erom neve ,esuap ot nosaer emos raeb eht evag sihT
.deksa eh ”?seluJ ,ereht KO uoY“
.teef nwo ym no deppirt I tub ,deneppah tahw onnud I dna ,ni klaw I dnA
.seluJ dias ”,seY“ .deksa eh
.ecaf sih fo tser eht ot neht dna ,eye thgir sih dna eye tfel sih neewteb detrad seye sih sa raeb eht gniyduts yltnetni ,sdnoces wef a rof ereht deyats ezag siH
”!trap eht kool yletinifed uoy :tahw uoy llet ll’I ,lleW“ .dias eh ”,gnorts leef ot tnaw tsuj I“
,eilrahC ot pu kcab dekool eh nehw ton ro dluohs eh rehtehw tuoba gnirednow saw eH
,fo kniht dluoc eh emit tsrif eht roF
.krims eltneg a otni gninrut elims sih ,tsehc sih fo tnorf ni smra sih
.dednim eh yas ton dluoc nailuJ esuaceB
,enin erew uoy ecnis mih morf draeh t’nevah uoy taht no pirg hguone gnorts a tup dna rehtaf ruoy ot klat uoy tel neve t’ndluow ehs fi ,taht gnisnes osla m’I .uoy no erusserp fo tol a saw ereht esuaceb gnitamilcca llits er’uoy esnes eht teg I tuB“
.taht ot denetrohs eb dluoc ti wonk neve eh did ron
thgim uoY .kciuq laer etis eht ezilirets attog oslA“
.enif eb ll’uoy ,ylsuoires tuB“
.erew yeht erehw ot esolc rood a ot derutseg neht eH ”.sthgiew
.noitom eno ni eb lla ll’ti tub
.sdneirflrig-xe sih neve dna ylimaf dednetxe sih ot srehcaet sih morf ,nailuJ mih dellac ydobyreve ,siht fo esuaceb ,esruoc fO
.noitazilaer ni gniddon erofeb ,deknilb eilrahC
”.uoy dedneffo taht fi yrroS
.yllausac deggurhs eH .eilrahC dias
,tops sih ot detoor mih tpek taht msitengam eht nialpxe ton
.gnihctaw saw ehs taht gnileef eht ekahs ton dluoc llits eh won dna
”?emit taht htiw od ew dluow tahw ,snepo neve rab eht erofeb llik ot sruoh wef a evah eW“
.nepo kcap eht erot ehs sa ylkciuq gniggurhs ,nrut ni delims yentruoC .dias eh
.s’nailuJ ot resolc reve gnidils dnah sih ,deddon eilrahC
”,yltnecer erom ylnO“
”?yadot gnihtyna gniod …hu ,uoY“
.eilrahC ta pu gnikool erofeb rab eht no dah eh setalp fo tnuoma eht ot revo gnikool ,deddon nailuJ
,ti tog eh taht won dnA
:ereht nam yreve dessalctuo eh tcaf eht naht erom saw ti ,hO
.redluohs eht no seluJ dettap neht ehS
.nailuJ ot derutseg eH
”,nwot fo trap siht nI“ ”.draeh I tahw morf
.erofeb ronaemed s’anut eht ni nees ton dah eh taht dnik gnihtemos was nailuJ ,seye eulb-yks esoht nI
…hguoht ,uoY“ .deggurhs eH
.kcab denael eH .deilper eilrahC
”!flesym ot lla uoy teg I esuac‘ ,yug gib ,ereh esle enoyna fo suolaej tsomla m’I“
,ot decrof saw I ekil tlef tI“
”.garb ot emit eht ekat t’nod uoY
.rehtaew yllihc rof detius retteb eb ot dnet seiceps ruf emos taht tegrof syawla I ,thgiR“ .deddon eilrahC .dias eh ”,ruf raeB“ .nwod trihs sih dellup eh sa sworbeye sih gnitfil ,eilrahC ta decnalg nailuJ
,eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL dna tooB
”,tuo ti ekat em ekam yletaidemmi d’ehs
”.esu d’I sthgiew eht htiw myg a dnuof yllanif I dalg tsuj m’I“
”,gnicreip worb a gnitteg
.edis eht ot deralg eilrahC .deksa seluJ
.sretteL amginE ehT noitcelloc yrteop eht sa llew sa
.decrof gnileef tpek I yhw nosaer a saw ereht fi
”.sreniart lanosrep ruo fo eno s’eH
,edis eht ot daeh sih detlit neht wehttaM
.tey gniht dab a ro gniht doog a saw taht fi wonk ton did raeb eht tub ,taht tuoba gnicreip
deciton evah ton dluow nailuJ
”?taht wonk’y ,etuc yllaer er’uoY“
”,era meht fo tsoM“
.kcab deleep sdnah reh ,neht dna
.rethgirb neve demaeb seluJ tuB
.ylthgils tuo eglub tsehc taht gnittel dna mih fo tnorf ni smra sih gnissorc ,delkcuhc eilrahC ”.thgirla …m’I“
.deddon neht ehS
.delahxe eH .deilper nailuJ
.gnihtyreve mih gnillet saw anut hsiugor siht gniteem fo sruoh wef a nihtiw siht gniod saw eh taht tcaf eht
:ksa uoy erofeb dnA“ .denworf neht eH
?erom tuo gnidnif morf kcab meht gnidloh saw tahw ,gnol os rof rehto hcae nwonk ylno dah yeht fi neve tuB
…dna tseretnisid sih fo tluser a sa ni neeb reve d’eh pihsnoitaler elgnis yreve ffo gnikaerb pu dedne eh dna ,mih rof gnihton did nemow ,lla retfA
.ereh emoc neve ot yaw eht fo pets yreve rehtom ym thgif ot dah I ,neht neve dnA
,ni depmuj uoy tsaf woh htiw ,esac ruoy ni dnA“ .dias ehs
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ni gnimoc saw I nehw ylsuoires ti ekat ot uoy tcepxe t’ndid I“ .eilrahC dias ”,haeY“
.reh htiw sgniht fo tol a tuoba erus ton m’I“
.yug gib ,ereht yeH“
:rorrim taht otni dekool seluJ
,ni delttes ,trap sih rof ,anut ehT
:nailuJ dellac gnieb dekil yllaer reven dah eh ,tsenoh yletelpmoc eb oT
.trap siht ot tog eh emit eht yb derob dekool dna dednuos elpoep tsoM
.ereht ruf eht woleb dna evoba elbisiv erew sllab elttil owt
”,kool ot erehw wonk uoy fi ti dnif nac uoy ,hO“
.hguorht ecreip ot gnitiaw tniop eht rof ti gniraperp
----**---- .kcab eht ot eilrahC gniwollof ,pu doots raeb eht ,siht htiw dnA ”.esruoc fo
.ylthgils hsulb ot raeb eht desuac sihT
.drawrof denael eh sa mih ta yldaorb gnilims anut eht ,mih ot txen loots a ta tas eilrahC
.tsap deklaw eh sa dehsulb ohw lee rellams a yb gnissap
.denrub sniev sih ni doolb eht thgirb woh fo erawa saw eh elahxe siht ni dna ,delahxe eH .deilper seluJ
,eireganeM oirT htiw mrofrep meht ees osla nac uoY
.delahni eh sselehtreven tub
.yawa edaf ssensuoicsnoc-fles eht fo emos gnileef ,feiler ni dehgis ,revewoh ,nailuJ
”.desu ylhserf si eldeen siht tbuod on s’ereht os tsuJ“
.srae sih dniheb tsuj gnibbur raeb eht ,deilper nailuJ ”,seY“
.sdnarts esoht morf emoc yticirtcele egnarts a gnileef fo tuo tub ,ssensuoicsnoc-fles fo tuo ton saw ti ,ylegnarts tub
thguoht gnicreip worbeye ehT
,uoy ekil si ereh enoyreve fI“
.pu dekool eh sa gnilkcuhc ,daeh sih koohs eH
.ecaf sih ot gnimoc krims a ,deddon eilrahC
,resopmoc a si ohw ,kcezzoW rreH yb
nam a morf ti gnitteg won saw eh tcaf eht
,elcsum erup fo edam saw ti ekil dekool sselehtreven
.efil sih fo yad yreve tsomla nailuJ mih dellac dah rehtom sih
”.no detsisni mom tahw s’ti tuB
.tekcap delaes eht ni retehtac dna eldeen eht gnikahs ,detats lanidrac eht ”,ereH“
.raeb eht ot kcab denrut wehttaM
…kniht I“ .deggurhs eH
:denetsil eilrahC taht tcaf eht saw ereht dnA
”.neht ,degnahc teg dluohs I“
.dniheb tfel saw rab elttil a esnes dluoc seluJ dna ,taerter retehtac eht tlef seluJ
.drawrof denael neht eH .dias eh
:mih tuoba sgniht fo stros lla gniciton ,desuap eh ,anut eht revo dekool eh sa ,tcaf nI
,gniwollaws ,delahxe eH
yag sih lla fo selat gnitaler
.worb sih ecreip eldeen eht tlef seluJ
.roolf eht ot gnicnalg ,delahxe nailuJ ”.gniog …s’tI“
.meht fo owt eht neewteb delttes ecnelis A
”.dliw s’eh ekil sdnuoS“
.dezirogetac eb tonnac
,yppah uoy sekam yllaer krow mliF“ .deddon seluJ ”.nialpmoc
.edis eht ot gnicnalg ,delahxe eH .nailuJ dias ”,sey-
,sdrawretfa yltrohs yreV
,ereH !ti eb dluohs taht dna ,elahxe ,thgirlA“
,worb sih fo hself eht gnola ylthgil yrev ezeeuqs recreip eht tlef eh erofeb ,deddon neht eH
.lasoporp s’eilrahC gniredisnoc ,desuap seluJ
.dehcaorppa eh sa denediw elims taht dna ,mih ot denrut neht eilrahC
.thgil eht ni yltnaillirb enohs seye eulb thgirb sih dna
,lleW“ .redluohs sih no gab myg sih gnitsioh ,delahni neht eH
”…gnorw gnihtemos od reven dluow I reh erussaer ot dah ,wollof
.retnuoc eht dniheb neeb dah ohw tar ralucsum rehtar eht ot denrut eh
”.ereh revo rood siht hguorht era srewohs dna srekcol ehT“
.uoy rof snoitseuq ruoy fo yna rewsna t’nac I“
.kcohs ni ediw seye sih ,rehtegot sdnah sih debbur eilrahC
.yawa thguoht taht reets uoy pleh ot ereh su tog ev’uoy ,os fi neve dna
.sevlesmeht rohtuA eht yb uoy rof daer
,pot-knat sih fo parts eht detsujda nailuJ
”.yllautca ,ti ekil I“
:enoyna morf alocasneP ni kcab noitnetta fo dnik siht tog ylerar eH
.sgel denot ylemertxe eht ta dna
.tuo dnah tfel sih deyalps ylsuoicsnocbus eh taht os hcum os ,mih otni pees ot nageb noitapicitna ehT
”!eno eht s’taht ,puY“
”,eno gib a s’eh ,hoO“
.delims gnortsmrA seluJ
neht eH .dias seluJ ”,ees I“
.nailuJ si siht ,eilrahC“
,tnaem msitengam eht tahw tuoba thguoht eh sa tuB
.dias eh ”,erus …toN“
.delgo eb ro elgo ot rehtie myg eht od syug semitemoS“
”,ffo gniwohs erew uoy gnimussA“
.em htiw eno-sulp a gard t’nac I yhw ees t’nod I tuB“
;tahw uoy llet I dna ,won sraey thgie ,neves tuoba ytic siht ni neeb ev’I“
.gnileef taht tuoba lufrewop
”…tfel ehs retfa mih ot kaeps em tel reven ehS
:taeb a piks traeh sih tlef eh tub
.dnuos ylevol yllaer a dah ti taht dezilaer eh
?rewsna ot esufer yllaer raeb eht dluow
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
N“ ”?uoy evah ,rab yag a ot neeb neve t’nevah uoY“
tuobA“ .deksa eilrahC
”.dne eht ni tuo skrow llA“ .deggurhs eH
.roolf myg eht si ereh oS“
.delkcuhc yentruoC
elpoep thgiarts taht si reeuq eht dna
.ylthgils derettuts d’eh gnizilaer nopu dewollaws nailuJ ”.olleh-
----**---- .skcol eht edisni syek dah srood moor rekcol dekcolnu eht lla taht
”.elihw a rof ti tuoba gnikniht neeb d’eh dias ohw enoemos yllaicepse dna ,ezis ruoy yug a morf sevren fo level siht tcepxe t’ndluow I“ .dias ehs
.dias eh ”,seluJ hO“
.deggurhs eilrahC
.anut eht ta delims eH
,kcezzoW rreH yb
.oN“ .delahxe nailuJ
.deggurhs eilrahC .deksa eh
.edis eht ot gnicnalg raeb eht ,deggurhs nailuJ
.denetsil eh sa noitartnecnoc ni detlit daeh sih ,srekcol eht yb doots eilrahC tuB
ylirassecen tsum
.yllufituaeb seye sih detnemilpmoc revlis eht dna ,thgil eht ni ylthgils denetsilg yehT
,moor rekcol eht fo tuo gnippets ,sredluohs sih dellor neht eH
.deddon seluJ ”?ydaer uoY
.noisufnoc s’nailuJ dedrager eh sa edis eht ot daeh sih gnitlit ,deknilb anut ehT
,mih htiw sgniw nekcihc gnitae
.pu doots eilrahC
.ti fo trap errazib tsael eht wohemos saw
tey egnarts eht gnileef
”?AL ni sboj mlif eht lla t’nerA“
”?srolrap gnicreip yna wonk …uoy oD“
;ecnelis elbatrofmoc ylemertxe na saw ti dnuof seluJ
,mih ot txen anut ralucsum eht tsuj saw ereht litnu ,yawa debbe dah rehtom sih fo sthguoht ,ylwols
.rehtegot emit erom dneps yeht ecno seog ti woh tuo dnif ot
,taht spleh taht nemiger a evah ew esimorp t’nac I ,lleW“
.elpoep reeuq era ereht sa
,anut siht rof gnillaf flesmih sdnif seluJ sa ,emit txen ni enuT
.syaw ralimis ni seidob rieht gniyfidom otni ylivaeh erew osla snoititepmoc nemgnorts sih ta nem eht fo emoS
.eilrahC sdrawot nwod osrot sih denael eh erofeb gniw nekcihc rehtona otni gniraet ,yldetnetnoc dehgis seluJ
.edis eht ot gnicnalg ,dehsulb seluJ ”.on-
siht htiw elbatrofmoc ton er’uoy fi on yas nac uoy dna—
,esle gnihtyna naht
”.nrob saw I erehw s’taht dna ,robraH yabhtooB ni pu werg rehtaf ym
gnilahni ,myg wen eht otni deklaw gnortsmrA nailuJ  2 fo 1 traP
”.enod s’ti nehw retteb tol a leef ll’uoy ,em tsurt tuB“
,trofmocsid elttil a leef ll’uoy neht dna ,tib elttil a gnits lliw sihT
ni saw eh tcaf eht fo esuaceb suovren ton saw eH
?ereh tuB .ereht edam gnieb mlif laitnatsbus laer on s’ereht dna ,pmud llams a fo dnik s’dnaltroP
noitats krow reh morf eldeen dna retehtac a debbarg ehs sa flesreh deirrac ehs yaw eht tub ,nem htob yb defrawd saw ohw lanidrac elttil ynniks rehtar a saw ehs
.delkcuhc eilrahC
”.em gnihctaw llits s’ehs ekil leef I semitemos tub
,rehtom sih fo sthguoht neve ton ,gnihton dnA
.dias eh ”,esnes taht ni ti gniyas ton m’I ,yug gib yrrow t’nod ,yeH“
”?gnitsujda uoy era woh ,aera eht ot wen
.ecaf reh fo srehtaef yerg eht revo lla gnitnilg sllab revlis
.neht erofeb ’lufituaeb‘
dluoc eH .eilrahC morf yawa pets ot ron
”?huh ,gnineppah yllaer s’ti eveileb t’naC“
,oottat eht no deregnil ezag sih sA
raeb ehT .mih rof pecib sih dexelf eilrahC sa yawa ezag sih llup ton did eh emit siht tub
.notsoB ni desab retirw dna ,tsinimerehT ,tsiloiv
.eilrahC ot dekool eh sa yltfos gniwollaws ,delahni eH
.ylsuovren tser mra eht no gnimmurd sregnif sih ,delahni seluJ
.seye sih desolc seluJ ,siht htiw dnA
.daeh sih gniddon ,delkcuhc eilrahC
yllaer I“ .roolf eht ot ezag sih denrut eH .deilper
.ylwols deddon eilrahC
,relevart wollef ruoy
:mih ot nrut ezag s’enoyreve tlef eh ,gniht eno roF
”.dab oot t’nia ti ,ereH
.emit eritne eht dnah ’seluJ fo og tel reven dah eh taht dezilaer eh taht neht ylno saw ti dna
.yltneg s’eilrahC tsniaga dehsurb eenk sih sa dedivorp dah retiaw eht etalp reziteppa elttil eht otno senob eht gnissot ,gniw nekcihc rehtona ta erot raeb ehT .nettog dah yeht elbat htoob eht ni mih ot txen morf eilrahC ta revo gnilims ,deddon seluJ ”.I nac rehtieN“ ”.mih
tey dna ,sdneirflrig-xe sih htiw siht enod evah reven dluow raeb egral ehT
.hguorht nees neeb dah eh noisserpmi eht evig thgim taht gnihtemos yas ot gnitnaw ton ,gnisuap flesmih dnuof eh dna ,ecno dehctiwt waj rewol siH
,trihs sih fo seveels eht yortsed ot denetaerht taht selcsum mra eht revo decnalg seye sih
tuoba suoiruc neeb ev’I“ .delahxe eH
.sevolg xetal emos no dellup ehs sa deilper lanidrac eht
.sworbeye sih esor eilrahC .dehsinif eh
—dluow enoyna yaw on saw erehT
.mih draeh enoemos ekil tlef seluJ
.hguoht ,taorht sih ni tlef eh noisnet llams eht pleh ton dluoc llits eH
.dluoc yeht thguoht reven eh yaw a ni ylthgils gnikahs sredluohs sih ,ylwols delahni raeb ehT ”…dnA
”…ti tuoba kniht I taht woN
,edistuo deppets eh nehW
.dnaltroP morf ereh revo devom I nosaer eritne eht s’tI“ .eilrahC dias
,kcezzoW rreH yb
detciderp eb tonnac hcihw eno
”,taht wonk I ,esruoc fo ,haeY“
devolg esoht tlef eh sa mih ta gnilims anut eht enigami tsuj dluoc seluJ
”.selohssa yllausu er’yeht tub ,semitemos ereh dnuora semoc taht skcoj elam ahpla esoht fo eno ekil kool tsuj uoY“
”?thgir ,ti rebmemer uoy dnA“
lleW“ .rehtegot sdnah sih gnibbur ,deddon eilrahC
”.taht fo derit tog osla I dna ,wollahs dna latnemgduj yrev era ereht syag eht fo tsom dna ,efilthgin s’ytic siht t’nsaw ti tub ,KO saw efilthgin yag eht tsael tA“ .dehgis eH ”.tsaf
,floWcaM boR si sihT
”,thginrevo doohrobhgien fo dnik siht ot gnivom ot desu teg t’nac ay ,yeH“
,deedni taht dezilaer eh
.rab yag eht ot yaw eht no doof tsaf emos teg ot tnew htob ew depparw dah toohs eht retfa os ,taht retfa tol a gnittahc ot tog htob eW
.ecno ti gnittap ,delkcuhc anut eht
.aera rekcol niam eht ni dewolla ton si gnikcuf ,on
.ecrof lluf denruter elims s’eilrahC ”.si ti seluJ“
,hguone gib tnempiuqe dah taht myg ylno eht saw siht …sihT“
”?sseug I ,tsaf noitnetta sih tog tahT“
”?huh ,nwo ruoy no emit tsriF“
.sraey eht revo nettog dah eh dehsiw eh taht eno
”?ew t’now ,thginot xif ot evah ll’ew ecneirepxe na s’taht neht ,lleW“ ”.t’nevah I“
gnihtemos saw ereht dna
”?suoivbo taht saw tI“
”.yaw taht detfig etiuq s’eH“
;erutalucsum evissam s’nailuJ ta gnikool ,smra sih dessorc eH
”?ecnis kcab neeb t’nevah uoy dnA“ .deksa eh ”?yllaeR“
”.thgir tuoba sdnuos taht os ,ay rof gniog rehtie evah t’now uoy
.mih dellac eilrahC tahw ta hctiwt rae sih gnileef ,deddon nailuJ
.seye eht ni yltcerid daehtsaM eilrahC gnikool ,edis eht ot decnalg eh ,sdnoces wef a retfa
ro ot dedeen yeht naht hcraeser erom
.dewollaws eilrahC ”.hO“
.eilrahC tuoba elttil suoicerp wenk eh
.daeh sih denrut eilrahC
,srood s’myg eht deretne d’eh ecnis emit tsrif eht rof dnA ”.em ot saw ti sa
”.yug gib ,em rof peed ni ehtaerb ,thgirlA“
?nam a revo tsriht ot ekil saw ti tahw siht saw :deknilb eH
mih ta dekool nam yreve hguoht neve dna
,tliub sa etiuq ton
.nialpmoc t’nac I os
.seralg evissimsid reh htiw laed ot dah raeb eht
.tcnitsid yrev dna ,tniop eht ot ,trohs
.ereht noteleks sih ta gnileef ,worb sih dnuora ni evom sdnah s’recreip eht tlef eH
taht gniees dna kcar ybraen a no setalp emos ta gnikool ,delahni yllanif eH
----**---- ”?ereh morf rolrap siht si raf woH“
.ylsuovren gnilkcuhc ,kcab deraer eh neht dna ,deknilb eilrahC .deksa eh ”?seluJ“
.nailuJ ot denrut neht wehttaM
”.nemow htiw pihsnoitaler a dloh reven dluoc I
.pu dekool neht eH .dias eh ”,KO“
.deksa nailuJ ”?rof tahW“ ”.yrroS“
,taeb a piks ot traeh s’nailuJ desuac noitnetta gniyap saw llits eilrahC taht tcaf ehT
.eilrahC sdrawot denrut nailuJ ,os dnA
detnecca liat sih yaw eht ,pot-knat nwo sih fo tuo deglub tsehc sih yaw eht
.ereh kcab emac dna ytic taht htiw pu def yletulosba tog I erofeb shtnom eerht rof ereht devil I dnA“ .dias eh
.tsrif metsys ruoy ni doof emos teg s’tel ,no emoC“
,regnarts latot a no pmud ot tol a saw siht fo lla wenk eh
”.tsaf siht ton yllaicepsE“
.nrecnoc fo kool a yb ylno decalper
”.seye ruoy esolc ,thgirlA“
.rae sih dniheb dehctarcs eh sa gnilahxe ,hcneb tuokrow ybraen a ot revo decnalg eH .nailuJ dias ”,seY“
.suoicsnoc-fles elttil a tlef llits eh
”.elihw a rof esuoh reh ni devil I .won yllaicepsE
.tey tsuj raf taht og dluoc eh fi derednow seluJ
dias dah eh tahw fo hcum woh derednow eH
”!seluJ ,yawa erolpxe
.teef sih raen gniregnil ezag sih ,dnuorg eht ot dekool eH .nageb raeb eht
”?ereh dnuora doog s’taht wonk uoy od tahW“ .dias eh ”,eruS“
”,teg dluoc ew stseuqnoc tahw ees ,thginot rab yag eht ta dneirf a htiw pu teem ot gniog saw I ,lleW“
”!erus rof retniw eht ni dloc steg yletinifed taht ,haeY“
”!eno dnim reven ,sper ynam taht rof taht tfil yllautca enoyna ees ot gnizama llits s’tI“ .deilper eilrahC
,kool fo dnik tnereffid a saw siht
”,haey hO“ .deksa raeb eht ”?huh
”!thgiE …neveS …xiS …eviF“
.noitale ni pu gnithgil seye sih dna thgil eht ni gnitnilg hteet sih
.lufituaeb saw nam siht
…ev’I“ .nwod decnalg eH
”.kcab gnidloh erew uoy gnihtemos saw ereht gnileef a dah I“ .deddon eH ”…ees I“
”,thgirlA“ .deddon seluJ
gnidiug ,rab eht rof emac sdnah s’eilrahC taht emit ni tsuj saw tI
”?yhW“ .dias eh ”,haeY“
.worbeye sih gnitcepsni ,drawrof denael yentruoC ”.KO“ .dias eh
,yadot sevirra eh nehw em rof taht od ot ereh teg ot dneirf a deksa ev’I os ,rettops a rof deksa uoy wonk I“ .hctaw sih dekcehc neht eH
.deifisnetni ylno elims ’seluJ
.daeh ym hguorht teg ot gniyas saw ehs tahw rof elihw a koot ti dna ,hteB
,elihw gnol a ni emit tsrif eht roF
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?thgir ,ti ot desu era uoY“ .desuap eH
”?taht saw oga gnol woh dnA“
,sdapwap sih tsap dehsurb yeht sa sriah eht fo erawa yletuca erom saw eH
.lamrof oot sleeF
”?rehtoM“ .deddon eilrahC
dna mih naht retrohs tib thgils a gnieb etipsed ,taht timda ot dah
”,elpoep no tceffe taht sah ylniatrec eh dna ,elihw a eilrahC nwonk ev’I“
,evorppasid ot ereht eb ton dluow rehtom sih dezilaer eh sa dnA
syaw ynam sa eb dluow ereht taht
.ksed noitpecer eht ot gninrut erofeb rood eht ta kcab gnikool ,delahni nailuJ
,siht ekil uoy ot ti wohs t’nod yeht fI“
?denrecnoc saw ti taht emit emas eht ta gnicreip eb kool a dluoc
”?taht tuoba leef uoy od woH“
”.dednemmocer saw tahw s’tahT“ .deggurhs eH
.deilper anut eht ”,raeh ot dooG“
.euqsetorg oot ton tub ,trohs saw tI
.wehttaM dias ”!si eh ereh ,hO“
…erugif sih tuoba lufrednow esle gnihtyreve detnecca tsomla elims sih yaw eht
.edisni retehtac a dna eldeen a htiw tekcap a detfil ehs dnoces eno ni dna ,ecnedifnoc fo trohs gnihton dewohs
”,ti raeh ot dalG“ .delims anut ehT
.gel sih nwod ekans dnah sih gnittel dna ’seluJ sdrawot daeh sih gninael
N“ .daeh sih gnikahs ,delims eh ,os dnA
;yas I os ,flesruoy erolpxe ot ereh emac uoY
.tuoba kniht ot tnaw ton did eh sgniht rehto niatrec
,redluohs sih otno ekans a d’oottat dah ohw snoititepmoc nemgnorts tsrif sih fo eno morf nogard odomoK ylrub rehtar a derebmemer eh ,ralucitrap nI
,rehtruf neve dehsulb nailuJ
.nailuJ dias ”,os ,hcum yreV“
”.emoh tog I nehw em ta lley dna
.thgil eht ni gnitnilg hteet kcub sih ,delims eH .dias eh
.gnihtemos fo thguoht eh
,worbeye thgir sih fo egde eht raen morf tub ,mih ta kcab derats ecaf sih
:sraey wef a rof eniaM ni pu werg I“
.roolf elit eht tsniaga toof sih gnippat ,nwod rehtruf decnalg eH
.wehttaM ot dekool neht eH .dias eh
.thgir tlef reven s’nailuJ“
”,aera eht ot wen ,thgir ,hO“
.dnah etisoppo sih htiw kcen sih fo kcab eht gnibbur ,edis eht ot decnalg eH
.seluJ ot kcab gninrut ,worbeye na esor eilrahC
ton ehs tsisni ot dah
…derednow seluJ dna ,ereh tnemgduj elttil yrev saw erehT
.rood moor rekcol eht ta kcab decnalg neht eH
”.hteB tem I retfa tsuJ“
”,wonk ot feiler a …s’tahT“
,revewoh ,ot gniklat saw eh ohw ees ot denrut nailuJ nehW
.ecaf sih ot rorrim a pu gnidloh yentruoC ees ot
.yaw yreve ni tcerroc yletulosba tlef wohemos taht htmraw neila na ,ylbaredisnoc pu demraw seluJ ni gnihtemoS ”.taert yM
devirra neve t’nsah eértne eht dnA“ .delahxe eH .dias eh
.tib elttil a mih desirprus
.seye s’eilrahC otni dezag eh nehw saw tahT
.eeuqram eht ta pu dekool eh sa yltfos
:ti htiw airohpue nwo sti thguorb siht dnA
.esirprus ni kcab daeh sih gniraer ,deknilb seluJ .dias eh
.ereht doots ohw yb draug ffo thguac ylneddus ,ylteiuq delahni nailuJ
”?hcum snoititepmoc namgnorts od uoY“ .deddon tar ehT
”…retfa alocasneP ot devom I dna rehtom ym dna ,hguoht ,enin saw I nehw tfel I“
.seluJ ta pu gnikool ,delims eilrahC
,thguoht siht htiW
,dneirflrig-xe tsal ym ot sknaht saw ehs gniraebrevo woh dezilaer ylno
”.taht od dna daeha og ll’I
.ti htiw detaicossa eh emahs eht htiw ton tub ,neht mih ot denruter
,ereh naht taht revocsid ot retteb erehw dna
.mih ni evah thgim eilrahC tseretni yna ot eud saw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”,tnaig deretlehs ,gib eht ,hA“
:etatiseh ton did seluJ
”.emit tsrif eht rof su ot gnimoc s’eH
.deksa eh ”?thginoT“
”.ereh ereves ssel tsuj s’ti
!yadot taht fo tes driht ruoy s’taht ,nmaD“
.rolrap gnicreip eht edisni riahc a ni nwod tas seluJ
”!ffuts epyt-namgnorts rof gniog erew uoy dias uoy nehw gniddik t’nerew yllaer uoY
.dnah tfel sih deyalps eh sa edis eht ot gnicnalg ,dehsulb eH ”…I“
.tnuocca ytiniffAruF rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.ti tog reven I oS“ .dias eh
.ni sdrow s’eilrahC koot eh sa gniggurhs ylpmis ,deddon nailuJ
:sneppah noitazilaer taht revewoh tuB
.ylraluger tfil dluow eh taht sthgiew hguone dah taht ecalp a saw ereht yllanif ,yllanif
dna pihW slevon eht fo rohtua eht era yehT
,tib elttil a tsuj nwod looc ot demees sniev sih ni tlef eh taht erif eht ,ylnedduS
yaw did rehtie yeht tcepsus d’I ,t’nerew yeht fI“
.deggurhs eH ”…tsuj I ,yrroS“
.no-daeh seye eulb-yks esoht gniteem ,eilrahC ta delims raeb ehT ”.haey-
.tib elttil a tsuj selcsum waj s’nailuJ denesool taht xodarap siht ni gnihtemos saw erehT
.deggurhs eH .dias eh
.htaerb peed a koot eh sa yentruoC ot gnikool ,deddon seluJ
.myg eht fo ydob eht otni gniklaw
:ecin tlef ti tub
----**---- ”.tnaw uoy reverehw tratS“
era yeht tahw dna
…won etal oot ,lleW
.deilper raeb eht ”,KO naht eroM“
:myg elttil gnimussanu ,llams rehtar a saw tI
esirprus emos htiw gniton dna rekcol a gnidnif ,moor rekcol eht otni deklaw eh ,siht htiw dnA
.no kcab trihs elcsum kcalb sih gnillup ,delahxe nailuJ
.yawa dellup lanidrac eht retfa neve deniamer sevren sih ni elgnit eht tub
ylekil ti kniht dluow sseug detacude nA
…nwot eht ni sdneirf
.daeh sih fo kcab eht gnibbur ,delkcuhc eH ”…hguoht ,woN
.deretne dah yeht bup llams eht fo tser eht ot tuo decnalg eH
taht htiw detsuahxe tog I
.deilper nailuJ ”,esoppus I“
”?thgir tlef reven tI“ .deddon eilrahC
.deddon eilrahC ”.haaaaA“
:esruoc fo ,wen gnihton saw tI
.sevlesmeht rohtuA eht yb daeR
.deilper wehttaM ”,ti tuoba em llet ,haeY“
?ylduorp galf wobniar eht welf taht myg a ni
.emaceb ti suoires woh dna ,tnew noitasrevnoc eht erehw fo tceffe edis a saw siht wenk nailuJ tub ,dnaherofeb nees dah eh taht yoj eht fo emos deppord dah noisserpxe siH
.wehttaM dias ”,daeha oG“
.dah eh gnicreip worbeye eht derebmemer erom eh tub
.seman tuoba ralucitrap era sklof wonk I
:dekil evah thgim rehtaf sih emankcin fo dnik eht saw tI
”?ereh taht dnif t’nod uoY“ .dias seluJ ”,ees I“
.seot s’ynnub siht ot txen thgir sllaf xob siht ,wonk I gniht txeN
”.nam fo tros taht gniniart ecneirepxe dah ev’I esuac‘ ,kcul ni er’uoy
.flesmih ni gnihtemos gnirevocsid yrt ot dediced yltnecer tsuj ylno dah raeb gnisopmi eht :myg yag a
.ecaf sih fo tuo riah etihw emos gnihsurb ,deilper wehttaM
rehtar saw mih ot emac noitazilaer siht yaw ehT
.rae sih dniheb gnibbur ,deddon nailuJ .deksa eilrahC
.erom tib elttil a gnixaler selcsum sih
.drawrof dehcoocs eH ”.ees I“
.derugif eh ,yllautneve ti ot desu teg d’eH
,niaga seye sih denepo yllanif seluJ ,neht dnA
,ho-O“ .deknilb nailuJ
.desolc d’eh dezilaer ton dah eh seye gninepo ,delahxe raeb ehT
.yltneg ni dehtaerb seluJ
,ereh ton s’ehs wonk I“
.lausu naht kcen sih ot resolc elttil a tis ti gnittel
:thguoht a dah eh ,hguoht ,tnemom taht nI
.emit fo tib a ti eviG“
,detnarg rof era yeht ohw gnikat fo yruxul eht evah
.tnereffid er’uoy
,os od ot deen gnisserp on saw
”.uoy no doog yllaer skool tI“ .deilper eilrahC
”,taht ekil gnihtemos htiw doirep tnemtsujda egnarts a syawla s’erehT“
”,mih decrovid ehs retfa …lleW“
:hguoht ,tnemssarrabme fo tuo ton saw tI
.did yletinifed ti ,hO“
”tnemoM A sekaT ylnO tI“
,ma I erehw ees d’ehs ekil …ekiL“
.mra s’eilrahC ot deoottat rohcna wobniar eht ot kcab decnalg suht raeb ehT
.efil sih ni tniop yna ta nevig reve d’eh elims eniuneg tsom eht
.skcar thgiew dna senihcam suoirav ta gnitfil dnuora lla nem ees dluoc eh ,edis eht ot ffo
gniniart namgnorts sih detrats eh nehw morf ,lleh mih evig dluow ehs semit eht lla derebmemer eh
”?haey ,ekil skool taht tahw ees s’tel
”?wehttaM eb tsum uoY“
.ylteiuq deddon seluJ
nailuJ ”,yppah reh ekam ot
”?wohs nug eht ot tekcit a detnaw osla uoy
.ffo tnemegagne eht ekorb eh emit eht yllaicepse dna detaitini eh pu-kaerb elgnis yreve ot
.sthgiew yvaeh dna senihcam fo tol a sah ,aera doog ytterp a s’ti ,won yb ti ees uoY
”.taht tuoba thgir ytterp eb d’uoy os
----**---- ”…yddub ,edir a rof uoy ekat em tel dna ,kcab tiS“
”?thgir ,nailuJ eb tsum uoY !ereht yeH“
”,oN“ .deksa eilrahC
.dias eh ”,esruoc fO“
”,htapoicos a er’yeht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
selcsum mra s’raeb eht yaw eht gniciton ,erutsop s’nailuJ revo decnalg eH .anut eht dias
.drow yreve gnizilanretni ,ereht thgir deyats anut eht tub
.dlohesuoh a sa evitcirtser ytterp saw ti
,evil I erehw raen erehwyna reh evah t’nod I taht won dnA“ .nailuJ dias ”,seY“
,yltneg gnilims raeb eht tfel taht noitazilaer siht ot mlac a saw ereht
thgiarts eht neewteb ecnereffid latnemadnuf tsom eht taht niatniam ot elbissop s’tI
.yas ot reisae smees tsuJ“
,eussi taht sah ecalp yrevE“ .deilper eilrahC
”.gnimoclew ydaerla s’ti kniht I neht
.deneppah esle tahw otni og dluohs eh fi gnirednow ,desuap eH
dessorc eH ”.lla retfa ,rab yag a si tI
uoy ot gnimoclew sa s’ti epoh I“
”.leef ot tahw erus ylluf ton m’I …m’I
”,yllaer toN“ .deksa raeb eht
,siht gnissecorp ereht tas eh sa dnA
,yltneg sih tsniaga hsurb dnah delacs taht tlef eh nehW
…tlef taht gnihtemos saw erehT
.yawa taht ekat dluoc
.siht od s’tel ,og ot ydaer er’uoy fi ,lleW“
”tnemoM A sekaT ylnO tI“
”…seod tI“ .deddon raeb ehT
.tuo mra sih gnikahs ,dexaler seluJ dna ,ecalp ni kcab saw rab eht ,kcalc a htiW
.eson sih evael trons llams a gnittel ,deddon seluJ ”!tey
,lleW“ .rehtegot sdnah sih deppalc eH .deilper eilrahC
.flesmih mlac ot htaerb peed a gnikat ,deddon nailuJ dnA
,efil sih ni tlef reve dah eh naht remraw leef seluJ edam elims ehT
,niatnuom etulosba na ekil tliub saw eh wenk nailuJ
.ruf s’nailuJ fo ssenkciht eht ta niaga decnalg neht eH .deilper eilrahC
Y“ ”.spmoc nemgnorts gniod eb dluohs ohw nam fo dnik eht yltcaxe era yllaer uoy ,gniddik t’nsaw ttaM“ .elcsum yreve denimaxe eh sa gniddon ,ecno nailuJ revo decnalg eH
?gnivol… …gnitivni ,mraw saw ti
”.ti nettog reven …tsuJ“ .dias eh
H“ ”?yadot gniod uoy era woH
.deksa eilrahC ”?ton yhW“
…fi ees ot ereh emoc ot detnaw I“
sselnU“ .oottat eht gnilievnu ,elttil a eveels sih no gnillup erofeb ,deggurhs neht eH ”.teY“
.redluohs eht no raeb eht gnittap dna hcneb eht tsap gniklaw erofeb ,delkcuhc eilrahC ,yllaniF
.gnola mih del tar eht sa
:mih ta level dluow rehtom sih erats hsrah eht ton saw sihT
ereht tub ,seohs sih otni teg ot dah llits eh
.lla ot deyalpsid saw ti ylduorp woh ot dna ,oottat rohcna s’eilrahC ot nwod detfird ezag sih
.ylkciuq yrev yawa dedaf ti tub ,dnah s’eilrahC no dezeeuqs eh taht hguone lufniap saw tI
,noitcudorp gib siht rof tes no yad artxe na dah I ,hguoht ,thginoT
er’uoy wonk I !s’grebdloG ot emocleW“
.thgir os tlef tsuj siht tub ,raeb eht ot citcamilcitna
.sredluohs sih evael noisnet gnileef ,delahxe nailuJ ”.hA“
.edistuo neve naht reillihc elttil a saw taht moor a ni neve ,mraw mih tpek
.pu sbmuht a tar eht gnivig ,deddon nailuJ
.troffe eht morf gnikahs smra sih ,pu kcab rab eht dehsup eh dna ,per tsal eht ta detnurg nailuJ
.sredluohs sih depoleved dah eh woh fo tcudorp edis a tsuj saw taht wenk eh tub ,ereht gniyats emit drah a dah syawla tI
,neht mih revo emac tahw wonk etiuq ton did raeb gnisopmi ehT
”,pleh t’nseod taewS“ .deggurhs nailuJ
.rovaedne hsiloof a saw siht :delahxe nailuJ
,ecaps nepo fo ytnelp :tcefrep saw tI
.deilper ehs ”,nur
,kcab ym ffo reh teg ot daH
Y“ ”?yug gib ,’seluJ‘ ay llac ot em ekil uoy dluoW“
,desuap nailuJ tuB
.detaerter eldeen eht sa trofmocsid emos tlef eh ,taht retfA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.elpoep rehto ees ot yaw a dnuof syawla dah eh ,esuoh s’rehtom sih ni gnivil nevE
”.selcsum ruoy ot neeb s’ti esolc woh htiw ,kciht fo dnik yllautca si ruf ruoy togrof I“
mih dniheb gnivaw liat gib a htiw ,anut ralucsum rehtar a saw eH
.kcar eht no ecalp sti ot kcab ti
”.dab ytterp pu toof sih degnab ev’dluow ylbaborp I ,retal sdnoces eerhT
”.efil yag siht gniees ot drawrof kool I nehT“ .drawrof denael
.gnola dewollof eh dna ,deppalc anut ehT
.ylsuoveihcsim dennirg eH .dias eh
,sexe sih sdrawot gnileef neeb evah dluohs eh tahw saw siht fi derednow raeb eht
,eton siht htiw dnA
.ecaf sih no noisserpxe desufnoc a htiw eilrahC ta gnikool ,denworf nailuJ
.mih sdrawot gninael tsomla saw anut eht taht ees dluoc seluJ tcaf ni dna ,eenk sih evom ton did ,trap sih rof ,anut ehT
.mra thgir sih no deoottat rohcna wobniar a dna
,ytilituf ni esicrexe na saw lavorppa reh rof gnikool taht detpecca yllanif dah eH
tam eht no tfos spetstoof sih ,dewollof nailuJ
,worb sih revo krow sdnah-walc
,sgnicreip worb nwo reh ot derutseg ehS
.mih teem ot tiaw t’nac I .dooG“ ”!puY“
”.rehtaew
”.yug gib ,eno siht rof seye ruoy esolc annaw
,sih ni dnah s’anut eht gnipsalc ,dnuora ti denrut eh
,ni gnihtemos wercs ot demees swalc s’yentruoC ,ylfeirB
”.ti ot desu er’uoy fi ,rehtaew dloc rof llew skrow ti sseug I ,llitS“
.tar eht ta gnikool ,delahxe eH
.lla retfa ,setunim ytnewt dna ruoh na tuoba rof regnarts emosdnah siht nwonk ylno dah eH
,rehtom ym htiw alocasneP ni kcab siht enod dah I fI“