.ylsuorogiv ti gnikahs dna sih ni ti gnikat ,dnah gib ’seluJ rof dehcaer tibbar ehT
”?thginot ecalp ym ot kcab mih ekat I fi dniM .etuc laer s’eH“
”!ereht og neve t’noD“
.ria eht ni regnif sih gniggaw ,dias eh ”,haaaA“
.moorhtab eht ot yaw sih edam eh sa tuo smra sih gnihcterts ,yawa deppets ylkciuq eilrahC
.deilper seluJ ”,sseug I“
”.yadot tuo-krow ym gnirud rettops ym eb ot eilrahC deksa wehttaM“ .deilper seluJ
,denworf kriK ”.gnicreip a dnA“
?em tuoba tahw tuB“
.sesuoh fo wor on htiw tub ,siht enigamI“
.devom eh sa mih dniheb gniyaws liat kciht sih ,ereht ni lriwt elttil a tif
.siht ekil eilrahC ssik syawla dluoc eh dehsiw seluJ dna
,staeb wef a rof mih dehctaw ylpmis seluJ dna ,lufyoj dna citegrene erom erew sevom siH
retirw dna ,tsinimerehT ,tsiloiv
.tuo yalp noitcaretni rieht dehctaw eh sa gnilahni ,kcab tas seluJ .tahc ot nageb yeht sa mih evael sevren s’netram eht dehctaw eh dna
erofeb ,tops s’kriK ta decnalg eH
.gniliec eht ta thgiarts gnitniop ,dehctiwt srae s’raeb ehT
”,thgin eht fo ruoh siht rof lamron yllautca si sihT“ .delkcuhc eilrahC
.daeh sih detlit seluJ ”.epyt nig
.seye sih gnisolc erofeb ,delims seluJ
,elbmaerp hcum tuohtiW ”…eilrahC“
.roolf ecnad egral a fo strikstuo eht no selbat eht fo tsom htiw ,ecaps ediw ylbidercni na osla
.ecaf sih no gniyalp elims daorb a ,deggurhs eH .dias eh ”,kriK
.erutan ni dnuora rednaw em tel tsuj
”,gniht efilthgin yag elohw eht ot wen fo dnik s’eH“
siht llac yeht egnartS“
,noitamrofni tcatnoc sih evah t’nod I
:detcepxe eh naht rekrad tib elttil a saw ecaps ehT
.seert yb dednuorrus deniamer seluJ dna eh taht naht rehto tub
.deilper kriK ”,sdneirf wen rof sknird gniyub evol I ,yeH“
.deilper anut eht ”,myg eht tA“
.ereh eb dluow yeht esiwrehto
.dias eh ”,setsat tnereffid evah lla ew dnif ll’uoy tub ,rab yag a eb yam tI“
.sevlesmeht rohtuA eht yb daeR  ?bulc eht ot
.srehto naht redwel gnieb emos htiw
”,sknird eht lla revoc ll’I
.ebircsed ton dluoc eh taht htmraw a htiw traeh sih dellif taht tuoba gnihtemos dna
.bulc eht ot revo gnitteg tuoba gnikniht trats dluohs eW“
.pu gnidnats erofeb reeb dnoces sih gninwod ,delahni eilrahC
,edis eht ot ffo osrot s’raeb eht ssorca neeb dah taht mra eht gnihcterts ,denway anut ehT
,ta dekool ylekil rehtaf sih tahw
.eilrahC ta dekool eh sa daeh sih gnikahs ,delahxe seluJ ”!tahT !seY“
derednow eh dna ,dehctamnu saw smra sih ni tlef eh elgnit eht tub ,ylthgils taorht sih fo kcab eht ni denrub lohocla ehT
,taht ekil knuh a roF“
,siht dias eilrahC sa noos sa dnA ”.em morf ro
.taeb eht ot osrot sih nwod dna pu levart ot nageb sdnah esoht tub
,eilrahC ot denrut noitnetta s’tibbar eht sa noos sa dna ,retaw fo ssalg a htiw ereht tas eH
noitcartta ot ecnereffidni morf nrut-renroc eht
.erofeb naht cnys ni erom gnivom meht fo owt eht ,retteb elttil a snoitom sih ezinorhcnys ot siht desu eH
.tsehc sih no rits eilrahC tlef eh ,flesmih yb noitseuq siht rewsna dluoc seluJ erofeB
”!eilrahC htiw ecnaD“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.pU smottoB fo eman etairporppa ylralugnis
.no gnimoc ssenkrad eht esnes ydaerla dluoc eh
,kcen sih pu nur sdnah s’eilrahC fo eno tlef eh
I“ .rae tfel sih dniheb tsuj gnihctarcs dna dnah eerf sih gnikat ,dehsulb seluJ
”,eurt s’taht sseug I“ .deknilb seluJ
.tuo edaf ot gnitrats tsuj saw egnaro eht taht gniees ,yks eht ta pu dekool seluJ
tooB dna pihW slevon eht fo rohtua eht era yehT .notsoB ni desab
”.sklaw gnineve rof tcefrep s’ti dna
,ti od ot ediced uoy fI
”.em ot tcefrep sdnuoS“ .deddon seluJ
uoy rof daer ,kcezzoW rreH yb ”tnemoM A sekaT ylnO tI“
”,si ti tahw wonk t’nod …I“
”,ti rof og yas I nehT“
.ylthgils rekaerbdniw sih tsujdaer ot ylfeirb gnitrap ylno
,ylwols ssenerawa ’seluJ deretne ylno ssik a saw ti tcaf ehT
,doog sleef ti tuB“ .dereffo eh
”?ereh raen evil uoY“
,semitemos siht ekil shtap gnola em ekat dluow rehtaf yM“
.myg eht ecnis os enod dah yeht emit tsrif eht ,tsehc sih no elttes sdnah s’eilrahC tlef seluJ taht neht saw tI
.tsehc s’raeb eht no dnah sih gnicalp ,drawrof denael neht eH
.daeh sih gnitlit dna seluJ ot gninrut ,deppots eh os dna ,noitseuq eht ta delkcuhc eilrahC
”?huh ,uoy htiw spirt no emoc ot em gniksa ydaerlA“
”.nwot dnuora wen enoemos gniwohs m’I dna ,taht ,lleW“
ees ot ssorca gnikool
.llet ot ylrae oot s’ti yas I
”.ecnis detrap ton evah …eW“
.htiw ecnad ot ekil eb dluow eh tahw
.taht retfa tuo llif ot bulc eht rof gnol ekat ton did tI
…a sa em ekirts uoY“
,ruf sih gnihcuot etiuq ton saw tI
”,hguone riaF“ .deddon kriK
.gniretaw seye sih ,dehgis neht eH
”?mih rof kool did I fi em htiw emoc ot gnilliw eb uoy dluow …dluoW“
,elims hsipeehs a dereffo neht eH
,degnoleb eh erehw saw eh ekil tlef eh ,fo kniht dluoc eh emit tsrif eht roF
.deksa eh ”?ereh ydoboN“
,deniart ton saw eH
.kriK ta dekool eh sa kcab gnileep ,deknilb seluJ
”.eman a dab taht ton s’ti ,won thgir ebyam tuB“
.emoh fo erom neve mih dednimer taht ycamitni fo dnarb niatrec a no deklaw yeht htap eht evag ti ,gnihtyna fi tuB
.daeh s’eilrahC dniheb hctarcs yltneg ot pu gnimoc dnah sih ,desuap eh ,ereht dial eh sa tuB
.yawa gnillup ton tub gnihsulb netram eht ,mih revo nael tibbar eht dehctaw seluJ
.gnola gnivom snoitom sih
.rab eht ni ecalp sih ta kcab gnittis ,siht ta worbeye sih esor kriK
”?uoy t’nod ,ti ssim uoY“
.drawrof gninael erofeb
.etats emoh sih ekil gnihton kool dluow ti noos neht dna
”,reilrae sdnah gnidloh erew uoY“
”,yug gib ereht yeH“
?noitautis siht fo eurt ydaerla t’nsaw taht od etad a ti gnillac dluow erom tahw
.seluJ ot resolc reve gnihcni ylwols saw eilrahC taht dezilaer seluJ taht neht saw ti dna ,mhtyhr a otno dehctal yehT
.niaga mih ot klat ot tnaw yllaer
”.gnorw eb reve dluow od dluoc I gnihton ekiL
neht ylno dnah ’seluJ fo og gnittel ,delims anut ehT
”…nosaer gib eno rof ,su rof doog osla s’ti dnA
!ti gniyojne s’eH“
.repeed mih gnillup dna daeh sih fo kcab eht otno gnilttes
.eilrahC dna kriK htiw ti gniknilc
…neht litnu yaw eht fo pets yreve ti dewollof d’eH
”,ereh dnim ni peek ot stnemtimmoc fo tol a tog ev’I“
”.ylevol yllaer saw tI
?thgir ,eniaM ni nwot latsaoc llams a s’tI“ .dereffo eilrahC
.egde s’roolf ecnad eht ot nwod seluJ del eilrahC ,siht htiw dnA
,roolf ecnad eht no ssik eht naht etanoissap erom elttil a saw tI
,eson sih elkcit htaerb s’eilrahC tlef eh woh
.efil elohw sih dah reve eh naht tnemom taht ni devol erom tlef ylneddus eh dna
.daeh sih gnikahs ,delahni eH
.knird sih fo tsal eht gninwod ,dekniw kriK tuB ”…I“
.deggurhs seluJ ,suhT
gniog rof noitaraperp ni
.ylthgils gnidaf elims sih ,edis eht ot decnalg seluJ ”?uoy dnA“
…gnidnatsrednu os ,eerf os ,nuf oS
.seluJ ot kcab denrut kriK
,elbmuh er’uoy ,emosdnah er’uoY
.deilper eilrahC ”,yltcaxE“ .dias eh
.pu sih dekcip eilrahC sa pu ti gnitfil
.dessik rehtar evah dluow eh
…niaga ti ees ot eb dluow ti doog woh dna
.delims seluJ ,flesmih fo etips ni dnA .nageb eilrahC
”?otni nrut ll’uoy nosrep eht ekil t’now I deracS…“ ”…deracs tsuj m’I“
?noisiced diputs a siht lla saW
”?yug gib ,dnim ruoy no ’nihtemoS“
saw ti taht tpecxe ,tey tsuj ti tuoba leef ot tnaem saw eh tahw tuo ekam etiuq ton
ocsicnarF naS dnuora eilrahC wollof ot nageb seluJ ,emit tsaL
:tniop taht yb worb sih decreip ydaerla d’eH
.gnitseretni taht eb ot gniog ton ylbaborp m’I
”,uoy ot pu s’taht ,lleW“
ni saw eh taht tcaf eht dna ,traeh sih demraw tI
.uoy tem I nehw yadretsey litnu syug dekil I hcum woh wonk yllaer neve t’ndid I
,em wonk uoY“ .guh a tibbar knip eht evig dna drawrof pets dluoc eh os
,ereh dneirf enisru ym rof skcor eht no nig eno ,ynoT“
.seluJ ta pu gnikool ,kcab tas neht eH .eilrahC dias
”,eurt s’taht sseug I“
.dias eh ”,haey tuB“
.tsaf ylbidercni gnivom lla saw siht dezilaer eh
.ylralimis od ot nageb anut eht sa eilrahC ta thgir gnikool ,seye sih denepo neht eH
,revewoh ,nekopssim dah eh fi gnirednow trats dluoc seluJ erofeB
.skeehc sih no kcab yaw sti dekrow hsulb tahT ”…ti pleh t’nac I …I“
”.gnihtemos ro tuctrohs
.onhcet eht yb dewollaws neeb dah sdrow sih diarfa
,ocsicnarF naS ni ekil kool dluow noitullop thgil tahw wonk ton did seluJ
”.ecnahc a s’erehT ?eeS“ ”.ot
pu emac hsulb llams a ,eilrahC sdrawot daeh sih dewob eH
.meht dias d’eh dezilaer neve eh erofeb htuom ’seluJ fo tuo emac sdrow ehT ”.em htiw ecnaD“
,eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL dna
”,yug gib ,ksa reven d’uoy thguoht I“
,hA“ .netram eht htiw gnitrilf yllufyalp saw kriK erehw
,gniod saw eh tahw wenk eh erofeB
?huh ,myg eht ta tem uoy oS“
.kriK dna eilrahC htiw gnivah saw seluJ taht noitasrevnoc eht fo tuo gniyats ,elihw a rof rumrum wol tnatsnoc a ta deniamer cisum ehT
:rehtie ,revo gnikool saw eilrahC
.tsehc s’raeb eht no sregnif sih demmurd eH
,ereht lesuoraC fo strap mlif did yeht dna ,nwot tsiruot a saw tI“
.seye eht ni anut eht
.eenk sih tsniaga pu pmub gel a tlef eH
,deniwtretni spil rieht noos dna ,ylthgils htuom sih detrap seluJ
.woh wonk t’nod I“
seluJ tub ,lla retfa ,detcepxe naht gnineve reillihc rehtar a saw tI
.tnuocca ytiniffAruF rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”?thgir ,gnidliuber htrow eit ylimaf a eb d’ti kniht I
,tlef eh tahw teg etiuq ton dluoc raeb ehT
”,epoh eht s’tahT“ ”?ffuts
,ffuber fo tros yna htiw ylper
seluJ lohocla eht dna cisum eht fo ezah eht ni dna ,ylwols detrap ssik ehT
.os od ot lliw eht dekcal eh rof
.elahw eulb gnikool-ciots rehtar a yb dennam saw rab ehT
srexob rieht ylno gniraew ,smra s’rehto hcae ni peelsa llef htob yeht os dna ,etal os pu gnieb ot desu os ton saw seluJ
.ti eldnah dluoc
.ereh thgir ecalp siht s’ti ,em roF
.gniggurhs dna seluJ sdrawot daeh sih gnitlit erofeb ,kcab denael eH
debbarg kriK .meht ni sknird tnereffid htiw lla
?mih wollof eh dluow raf woh tub
”?ydaerla etad a no tuo mih nekat ev’uoy dna yad a flah mih nwonk neve t’nevah uoY“
,netfo erom ytic eht fo tuo teg ot deen I em gnillet syawla si kriK tuB“ .eilrahC dias
.gnieb elohw sih emocrevo ssensuoicsnoc-fles fo tlob a tlef seluJ
”.taht erolpxe t’nac I emahs a s’ti tuB“
”.selim rof sesuoh on eb dluow ereht ,sliart emos nO
ot deganam eh :revewoh ,reerf hcum erew stnemevom siH
?ekat taht dluow gnol woH
.hctaw sih dekcehc eilrahC ”!dooG“ .dias eh
.esirprus ni gniknilb ,eilrahC ot txen rab eht ta tas suht eH
.noisiv sih fo egde eht tsap tsuj ees dluoc eh
.gnilims ,pu seenk sih dellup neht eH
gnitsohg tsomla erew yeht ekil ,rednet erom saw hcuot rieht ,hguoht ,ereH
”.mih dnif ot drah taht eb t’naC
:erofeb nees ton dah eh taht nam emosdnah siht fo edis a saw ti dezilaer osla eH
”.hguoht ,ti rof ydaer m’I“
:sdneirflrig-xe sih ot ekil saw eh tahw wenk eH
”.taht etaicerppa I …I“
”?evol ni siht…“ ”…tlef reveN
.deilper tibbar eht
.raeb eht gnihcaorppa ,delkcuhc eH
…elgna siht morf dekool ti lufrednow woh ,hO …elims s’eilrahC dnA
,srab erom wef a retfA
.mih fo daeha htap eht ot kcab gnicnalg ,eilrahC ta nwod dekool eH
,erehwyreve era yehT“
.ylhsipeehs kriK ot dias eh ”,uoy knaht …mU“
,did eh dnoces ehT
.htuom s’kriK ot rae sih gninael ,deddon seluJ
”?huh ,epyt yhs tub gnorts eht ,hoooO“
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.tuo sdnah sih gnidloh dna pu gnidnats ,demaeb yletulosba eh
.dnoces a rof gnippord elims sih ,deksa eilrahC
”?huh ,llew sa oot ereh dneirf wen ym taerT“
”.citnamor yllaicepse gnieb sa ti tuoba tuo skcits yllaer gnihtoN“
.tibbar eht morf yawa kool ton dluoc eh dnuof tub ,dehsulb netram ehT
”?huh ,gnilaeh fo shtnom eerht
,emulov ni pu dekcip yllaer ti ,elihw a retfa ,neht dnA
”!yug gib ,bulc eht ot emocleW“
.tfel eht ot dna nwod decnalg seluJ
.netram eht ot revo gniretnuas dna pu gnidnats erofeb ,rab eht dettap kriK ,siht htiw dnA
”?tsaf oot gnivom …siht sI“
.trihs sih no dniheb liart mraw a tfel sdnah esoht ekil tlef seluJ
.puc eht ni ebuc eci elgnis eht dna ti gnilriws ,pu ti dekcip neht eH
:gnihtyreve ekatrevo dluow yks thgin krad eht ,nooS
”,srevol ot gnitaler yllaitini neve t’nsaw ti ,yltcerroc llacer I fI“
…tseretni esol dluow eilrahC neht dna ,pu llaw d’eh dna
.raeb eht ot resolc flesmih gnillup ,deddon eilrahC
evol ot noitcartta dna
.s’eilrahC tsniaga gnihsam tsomla spil sih ,ni denael seluJ
”,taht ekil d’I“ .delims seluJ
,yawa leep ton did eh emit siht tub
,esirprus ni deknilb raeb ehT
rehtar a ta dekniw tsuj dah tibbar eht taht yltniaf deciton seluJ dna ,seluJ htiw kriK tfel sihT
.rehtegot sdnah sih gnibbur ,delkcuhc eilrahC .dias eh
.ylthgil yrev ruf sih tsniaga hsurb selacs sih gnileef seluJ
nac uoY .sretteL amginE ehT noitcelloc yrteop eht sa llew sa
,ssik eht nruter ot yppah oot ylno saw anut ehT
.eilrahC sdrawot daeh sih detlit eH .kriK dias ”,epoN“
”.tniop taht ta leef uoy woh ees dna rae yb ti yalp s’tel os
.rednetrab elahw eulb eht ot gnirutseg ,deddon kriK ”?taht evah yehT“
.dias eh ”,kriK ,em eb nac su fo lla toN“ .deggurhs eilrahC
.eilrahC htiw deb a gnirahs ylgnilliw ,saw eh ereht ,won dnA
”,mih ssim uoy ekil sdnuos tI“ .delahxe eilrahC
----**---- ”.secneirepxe wen oT“
,taht leef ralucitrap a bulc eht evag yeht dna ,selprup dna seulb krad suoirav fo erew sthgil eht
.spih s’eilrahC no dnah a gnicalp ,nwod dehcaer eH
,won era yeht sa dnof sa era mih fo seiromem ruoy fi dna
ta dekool eh sa gniwollaws ,nrut ni pu tas seluJ ”…ebyaM“
dluoc eH .rehtie lamron sa ti ebircsed ton dluoc osla eh
.nageb eilrahC ”,yreV“
ezilaer ew nehw tnemom eht naht elbaifissalc erom on si
”?thgir ,os od ot eerf er’uoy ,erutcip eht fo tuo rehtom ruoy htiw ,yeh dnA
.denruter yllanif elims siH
.elbissop kniht ton did seluJ deeps a ta sknird eht gniraperp ,deddon rednetrab ehT ”.bat ym nO
”.tsaf elttil a si ti fi nevE“
.sdnah s’raeb eht rof dehcaer eh dna ,redaorb reve werg elims s’anut eht
on saw ereht hguoht neve
.dnah ’seluJ fo kcab eht no ruf eht revo gnitsohg yltneg bmuht sih ,yldaorb delims eilrahC ,esnopser nI ”…tsuj uoY“
”.tuoba uoy gnillet saw I kriK dneirf ym si siht ,seluJ
:dnim ot emac thguoht siht sa desuap eH
,seluJ ,em ot gnitseretni ytnelp ydaerla er’uoY“
.tsehc sih ot pu dnah eerf sih gnillup ,eilrahC ot kcab denrut eH
eulb eht fo hguone tsuj gnitanimulli ,moor eht ssorca thgil egnarts rehtar a tsac yehT
.eye sih epacse raet a tlef eh dna ,delims seluJ
.seye sih desolc eh sa s’eilrahC no htuom sih gnitnalp
.edis eht ot gninael ,krims a htiw deilper
.dias eh ”,sknahT“
.yug gib ,ti tbuod t’nod I“
.dehctaw eh sa thgin eht rof nig dnoces sih gnippis ,delahxe eH
.mih nioj ot seluJ rof derutseg neht eH .rab
ylno kriK .niaga ecaf sih ot gnimoc hsulb taht
”.yug gib ,ti tbuod t’nod I“
”,robraH yabhtooB ot kcab og syawla dluoc uoY“
.yllufyalp deksa eh
,seidob gnitaryg fo ssam a emaceb ti ,ereht morF
.erofeb enoyna tuoba siht ekil tlef reven ev’I …tsuj I“
,relevart wollef ruoy
,esiwekil dnA .euqinu si
,tfel eht no teerts edis a otno denrut anut eht ,siht htiw dnA
.hcuot ot trats ylwols stsehc rieht leef dluoc seluJ
.kcab emac elims sih sa gniddon ,deddon eilrahC ”!sniw ydobyreve
,gnineppah gniregnil lautca
.ylevol etiuq saw tI
.edis eht ot decnalg neht eH .dias eh
.resolc mih gninokceb ,seluJ ot gninrut erofeb pu regnif eno gnitfil ,dekrims tibbar ehT
…m’I“ .daeh sih koohs eH .dias eh ”,sey-
.deb s’eilrahC otni delttes yeht sa
namgnorts ’niod uoY
.deggurhs kriK ”.si ti revetahw
,yawa gninrut dna smrah sih gnissorc ,deffuh eilrahC
.yaw a ni laiceps leef seluJ edam tI
,mih rehtob ton did ti did ti sa neve tub
,etaG nedloG eht ot pu seog ti
”?tey lohocla yna toG“ .dias eh
.seluJ dias ”,seY“ .deksa eh
”,yug gib ,nwo ruoy mih ekaM“
.deddon kriK  .deilper seluJ
,gnimlehwrevo eb nac bulc yag eht ni emit tsrif s’elpoep tsom wonk I tub
,rolrap gnicreip eht gnivael ecnis tsomla dnah s’eilrahC ot no dleh dah seluJ
.gnihsinav nirg ykcoc sih ,deilper eilrahC ”!kriK-
,evol hcae ,ti ekiL
era uoy ohw revocsid ot ekil d’I tub ,uoy tuoba wonk t’nod I dnA
,eilrahC ot deklat eh emit yreve tuB
.ydob ’seluJ revo lla gnirednaw deppots sdnah sih dna ,niaga moor eht pu til elims siH
.eep attog I ,syug yrroS“
.ereht erew sruf rehto wef woh gniton dna tuoba gnitrad seye sih ,eilrahC sdrawot denael seluJ
.em ot ecnereffid yna ekam t’now ti ,yaw rehtie dnA“
.daehtsaM eilrahC emosdnah eht htiw saw ti ,lla retfA
,daeh s’eilrahC sdrawot denael neht eH
.raeb gnisopmi eht ta pu dekool eh sa daeh sih gnitlit anut eht
.eilrahC ot dekool eH .deksa eh
,ekil sdnuos dna skool ti tahw morf tuB“
.sdnah sih debbur eh sa gninnirg ,rab eht ot dekool neht eH .dias eh
----**---- .htiw mih dellup anut eht sa gnola gniwollof seluJ
”.ecnad a rof pu eb ll’eh fi wonk neve t’nod I dna ,ffuts gnirevocsid llits s’eh
”?secalp
”…erom tib elttil a flesruoy otni worg uoy nehw ekil eb ll’uoy tahw ,ekil uoy tahw wonk yllaer t’nod I
.resolc mih gnillup ,spih s’eilrahC fo edis rehto eht ot dnah rehto sih thguorb seluJ ,ylwolS .rehtegot gnivom spih rieht ,yaw siht emit fo kcart tsol raeb ehT
,em rof revirdwercs eno
,tcejbus eht no tneps neeb sah taht kni fo tnuoma eht roF
tlef taht yad eht tuohguorht derahs dah eilrahC dna eh tahw ot gnihtemos saw ereht taht dnoces taht ni dezilaer eH
”?huh ,gnicreip ruoy ot deilppa noitulos enilas ruoy teg ylbaborp dluohs eW“
:delims eh ,did eh sA
.taht saw ti gnihsiw flesmih gnidnuof seluJ ylneddus tub
,tsaf yllaer gnineppah erew sgniht ynam taerg A
.ssik a derahs yeht sa nwod gniwols snoitom rieht
eht nevig saw hcihw ,bulc eht ot tog yeht emit eht yb krad etiuq saw tI
,eireganeM oirT htiw mrofrep meht ees osla
esuaceb ,tnaw uoy tahw od ot dewolla er’uoy nehw
.gnibbur sosrot rieht ,rehtegot dehsums suht erew spih riehT
,ssalg sih detfil eh ,os dnA
ton dluoc eh dnuof seluJ
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ekil saw ti tahw yltcaxe flesmih rof ees dluoc seluJ dna
.dehcaorppa eh sa rednetrab eht sdrawot denael neht eH ”.t’ndid
.trofmoc llams a saw tey yawa dellup ton dah eh tcaf eht tub
.yawa dedaf tesnus eht fo tsal eht sa gnihctaw ,yks thgin eht ta pu dekool eilrahC
,deilper eilrahC ”,tluaf a ot lanoisseforP“
.hsulb ot nrut s’eilrahC saw ti woN
,dnoces a retfa dna ,resolc werg sosrot riehT
.drawpu gnitlit rae tfel sih ,deksa eh ”?hO“
…hguone elpmis dekool ti dna ,ton erew ereht elpoep tsom denigami eh niaga neht tub
tsuj eh ,siht ekil ecalp a ot emoc ot thguoht syawla dah eh
ffo devom eh erehw wonk ylbaborp d’yeht ,devom eh fi nevE
.seidob gnitaryg eht ta kcab gnikool ,delahni seluJ
,sknird elpuoc a retfa roolf ecnad eht no nwod ti kaerb ot ekil yllanosrep I“ .deilper eilrahC
.sevlesmeht rohtuA eht yb
”.kcab thgir eb ll’I
.ecaf sih no gniworg krims gniwonk a ,kcab denael kriK tuB
”.yaw nwo ruoy ni dnik er’uoy gnihtyna uoy teb ll’I
.potretnuoc eht no knird sih gniees ,deknilb seluJ ”?sdneirf wen oT“
.seert eht fo spot eht ot dekool seluJ ”.od I“ .deksa eh
K“ .sthgil bulc eht rednu elbaecitonnu tsomla saw taht teloiv fo edahs a gninrut ecaf sih ,kcab deraer anut ehT
,hgual eltneg a dah kriK
,gnithgil eht ni nevE
”,enoyna dnuora siht ekil tca eilrahC nees reven ev’I“
.krap eht ni htap eht gnola deklaw yeht sa tekcop sih otni dnah eerf sih gnimmaj raeb eht ,no deklaw eilrahC dna seluJ
”.flesruoy era uoy ohw wonk ylluf t’nod uoy
.deb eht fo egde eht ta pu gnittis erofeb ,pu dekool neht eH
.timda ot dah eh ,etuc rehtar yllautca saw siht ekil tuop anut eht gniees
.ti htiw og tsuj ot saw denrael dah seluJ gniht eno tub
”!oga sruoh wef a tem ylno eW“
”!saw ti thguoht I sa wen sa si taht ,tihs hO“
”?huh ,eye sih thguac ydaerla s’enoemos ees I
.keehc sih fo ruf eht otni gnikaos erutsiom saw ereht taht gnirac neve ton ,gnilims flesmih dnuof seluJ dna ,detrap ssik ehT
”.ecnad s’tel ,ereH“ .dias eh
.delims eh ,did eh sa dnA
?llew sa eilrahC ot taht od eh dluoW
,daer ot drah noisserpxe sih dnuof seluJ
”.yug gib ,emit ynA“
.hguone llew rehto hcae wenk slacol eht
”?mih tcatnoc ton yhW“ .dias eh
,won robraH yabhtooB revo ekil dekool yks thgin eht tahw derednow eH
”.sgniht ot ylrae pu wohs ot evol I“
”?tsaf oot gnivom s’ti deirrow uoy era ,woN“
,t’nod uoy fi esuaC‘“ .dias eh
.roolf ecnad eht ot nwod yaw rieht edam lla erofeb tuoba gnillim erew taht sruf eht dna
…erom detnaw eh woh
tlef seluJ ylfeirb rof
,rof tiderc flesruoy evig uoy naht retrams er’uoy
.thgin taht bulc yag eht ot
.moordeb s’eilrahC ni sdnilb eht fo segde eht hguorht ni gnikeep nus eht fo syar eht yb pu nekow saw raeb ehT
,erutan eht tog ,seert tog s’tI
.yldrawkwa gnitfihs teef sih ,liart eht ot nwod decnalg raeb ehT
,sreltsuH nedloG ta mrofrep ot sah nerraD dna enecs a toohs ot sah sevY
”?emoh daeh dna srebmun erom elpuoc a ecnad annaW .hguoht
,tsrif ni denael seluJ
.ylisae etiuq devom eh dna ,evom ot nageb eh os dna ,sdrawretfa yltrohs rehtar pu denesool esle gnihtyrevE
.ylthgils denediw neht seye siH
.raeb egral eht revo dekool eh sa gniwollaws ,dnoces a rof ereht tas eH
erehw ezag fo dnik taht reven saw tI
Y“ .deknilb seluJ .deksa eilrahC
”.doog lla er’yeht dna
.kcab gnippets dna pu sdnah sih gnitfil ,dias eh
neht dnA .llew sa tsuj saw siht seluJ rof dna ,hguoht ,yzoc tlef tI
,sfi-tahw tuoba gnikniht ti dneps ot trohs oot s’efiL“ .deilper eilrahC
,tniop siht ot pu gnihtyreve htiw gnola enog dah eilrahC
.rab eht fo retnec eht ni gnittis tibbar knip ralucsum rehtar a sdrawot dellup saw noitnetta ’seluJ ,hguoht ,dehcaorppa yeht sA
,saw htuom sih esolc woh dnA
wonk I eno ylno eht s’taht dna ,myg dradnats s’eilrahC s’tahT
,meht fo tnorf ni spuc eerht deppord elahw eulb eht ,siht gniyas dehsinif eh sa noos sa tsomla dnA ”.ereh dnuora ysetruoc nommoc s’tI“
.esaelp ,anut eht rof reeb tfarc a dna
:tey demrof neve ton dah enil eht taht ylrae os devirra osla yehT
”—tog ev’I kniht I tub ,hguoht ,uoy tuoba onnud I“
,em ni ecnad erom emos tog llits ev’I“ .deilper eh ”,haeY“
ydobon saw ereht
.uoy tuoba hcum taht wonk yllaer t’nod I“ .dias eh
.retteb gniht elohw eht edam mih ot txen anut emosdnah a evah ot deneppah eh tcaf ehT
.sraet esoht yawa gnipiw sbmuht s’eilrahC tlef eh retfa noos rof ,ot emit eht evah dluow eh taht toN
.yawa gnicnalg ,dehsulb seluJ
.ydob elohw sih emocrevo redduhs a tlef seluJ
”…citnamor sselepoh a fo tib a er’uoy
.ylkciuq os neppah dluow ti detcepxe ton dah
.llef elims sih sa dnuorg eht ot gnicnalg ,delahxe eH
”.taht tcepser ll’uoy wonk I tuB“
.level repeed hcum a no tub ,taht ekil hcum
:mih ot htmraw tnasaelp yrev a thguorb tI
,sdnoces fo tsefeirb eht rof sih tsniaga hsurb eugnot ytlas a
…smra sih evaw ,spih sih etaryg ot hsiw eht
.kriK morf yawa gninrut saw eh nehw ylno saw ti neppah did ti fi dna ,ti ton saw siht dna
.nwod daeh sih dewob eilrahC
.lufrednow os tsuj er’uoy …er’uoY“
,knird nwo sih
,revo dekool eh emit yreve
”.gniog teg s’tel ,no emoC“
.uoy dnuora m’I nehw tnereffid leef I
.efil sih ni dah reve eh naht redaorb elims flesmih tlef seluJ ,siht dias eh sa dnA ”.em no s’ti nehT“
.nihc ’seluJ rednu bur ot pu dnah a gnihcaer ,delkcuhc eilrahC .deksa eh
.seluJ ta gnikool ,deggurhs eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.eilrahC ot dias eh ”?eeS“
”…dna ,gnitseretni taht ton m’I tuo dnif ll’uoy neht dnA
,esirprus ni ylfeirb knilb mih was eilrahC ta kool a ,sselehtreveN
,oS“  2 fo 2 traP
.yab eht si ocsicnarF naS fo trap tseitterp eht taht yas lliw emoS“
?tniop taht ta mih pots gnicnad tuoba sevren sih tel eh dluohs yhw os…
.eilrahC ot denrut eH
----**---- .cisum eht ot gnola ecnad ot deunitnoc dna ,kcab sdaeh rieht dellup meht fo owt eht ,siht htiw dnA
.eniaM ni pu worg did eh ,lla retfA
.thgilyad lluf ni erew yeht fi sa gninihs seye sih ,seluJ ta delims dna pu dekool eh erofeb
,srae sih ni dednuop ssab eht
.lohocla eht no trats daeh a teg ew tuB“
.bulc eht fo edis rehto eht no netram ehtil
”?eilrahC ,knuh siht teem uoy d’woH“
,pihsnoitaler hcae dna
.resolc gnihcoocs ,deggurhs eilrahC ,yllaniF
”,thgir ylbaborp er’uoY“
,mih htiw eltneg eB“ .deilper eilrahC
:deb ot thgiarts tnew yllaitnesse meht fo owt eht ,tnemtrapa s’eilrahC otni nettog dah yeht nehW
”.oot mih ekil uoy kniht I
.erew selohrae s’eilrahC demussa eh erehw ot elzzum sih devom eh sa esolc mih gnidloh
.elims a htiw deilper kriK
s’kriK hguohtla ,rab eht ot detoor deyats ssel ro erom dah seluJ dna ,eilrahC ,kriK
.ti tuoba tlef eilrahC woh erus neve ton saw eh tub
,eilrahC ot resolc flesmih llup ot deen eht fo tlef dah eh tsrif eht saw sihT
.tug sih otni peed delttes tbuod emos os dna ,syug pu kcip ot ereht erew yeht denoitnem eilrahC taht tcaf eht ot thguoht seluJ
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
latem fo tnilg eht dna ,worb sih ta pu gnikool ,rae sih dniheb debbur seluJ ”?ereh yaw eht no doof emos debbarG“
”.gniht fo tros taht tuoba suoituac yllausu m’I .esruoc fO“
.redluohs sih tap dnah delcsum a tlef eh sa depmuj seluJ
.kriK ot kcab denrut eilrahC
”.yaw taht eniaM fo em dnimer dluow tI“ .dedda eh
.anut eht ot gninrut erofeb ,pu kcip dluow ytrap eht erehw saw siht fi derednow seluJ
.thginot knird a uoy yub annog saw ,uoy no gnitiaw saw I“
.deton seluJ ”,’enaL s’revoL‘
.htuom sih fo tnorf eht ta tuo ekorb taht elims eht pleh ton dluoc tub ,ylthgils yawa denrut eH ”…I-
.yltneg dnah ’seluJ gnizeeuqs ,delims eilrahC
,ton ro etad a s’ti rehtehw oS
,uoy morf yawa taht ekat lliw yas nac enoyna gnihton dna
.sgniht hcus yned ot deirt nem taht netfo saw ti fi derednow eh
.eb ot sevlesruo emussa ot thguat erew ew sa thgiarts os ton era ew taht
.seluJ dias ”,esruoc fO“
.tib a etiuq rednaw did ezag
,duol neeb dah onhcet eht rab eht tA
,ydees sa ti ebircsed ton dluoc seluJ elihw
”?llew peels uoY“ .dias eh ”,yeH“
.erofeb naht tnenimorp erom saw eulb yks eht
,evom ot erised eht tlef eh ,ydob sih revo koot taht ezah eht htiw ,llarevo tuB
.sih ot esolc pu desiar erew smra s’eilrahC taht dezilaer eh neht dna ,cnys ni devom spih riehT
,tnemom taht tA
sgniht fo kool eht morf dna ,uoy sekil eh :yad sa nialp ti ees nac I tub ,ti timda t’now eH“ .dias eh
.dnoces a rof suoires gninrut noisserpxe sih ,daeh sih koohs anut eht tuB
”?strats cisum eht nehw sneppah tahw dnA“
.elims ylno dluoc
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.deksa eh ”?doohrobhgien siht nI“
teg yllanif meht fo owt eht nehw neppah lliw tahW
”.sa stnuoc ti llams woh wonk t’nod I os
”!ay htiw emoc ll’I dna wonk em tel
”tnemoM a sekaT ylnO tI“   :nigeb ot
”!ylrae er’uoy ,eilrahC“
.eilrahC ot nwod gnikool ,dehgis seluJ .deksa anut eht
.yltneg gnipeels eilrahC gniees nopu delims dna ,nwod dekool eh
”.hcraes tenretni na no pu nrut d’eh taht dleif hguone eliforp-hgih a ni yltcaxe ton si eh dna
.nam gib a hcus rof saw moor eht llams woh fo esnes a seluJ evig ot roiretni dellaw-
.pu flesmih dellaw syawla dah eh
.tsehc ’seluJ revo nwod bur dnah sih tel eilrahC ”.haeY“
.thguoht I erehw s’tahT“
edis eno no egnaro thgirb a denrub yks eht elihw dna ,yad fo thgil gninaw eht ni tuo doots ylniatrec yehT
.roolf eht ot gnikool ,delahxe eH ”…wonk t’ndid I
.reilrae ton did eh yhw derednow eh did eh sa dna
,ni htob erew yeht ,kcehc DI kciuq yrev a retfa
.hteB htiw neve ton ,tniop siht ot nettog dah ni neeb reve d’eh pihsnoitaler oN
.ezis ruoy syug rof sthgiew evah dluow taht
;tniop a tog ev’uoy sseug I tuB“
,resopmoc a si ohw ,kcezzoW rreH yb ”tnemoM A sekaT ylnO tI“
.mih ot denokceb taht eilrahC tuoba gnihtemos saw ereht ,myg eht ni tem dah yeht ecnis revE
”,yug gib ,pilc thgir eht tsuj ta ’nivom s’ti ,noitamitse ym nI“
.nihc sih gnibbur ,seluJ ot denrut eH
emos sa ti desu hsinapS eht kniht I“ .deilper eilrahC
,sesuoh fo wor a tsap tsuj pu dnats egdirB etaG nedloG eht fo sehcra eht ees dluoc eh ,meht erofeb tsuJ
,mih ot thgir tlef siht tuoba gnihtyrevE
.seluJ si siht ,kriK“
.ylwols yawa gnileep dnah sih ,yltneg ti koohs seluJ
”.efil ruoy fo tser eht rof ti terger ll’uoy
”.olleh-H“ .dias eh
.drawrof denael raeb ehT
.tsehc sih revo
yeht fi rab yttihs a eb d’yehT“
.seluJ ot denetsil eh sa tfos noisserpxe sih ,deddon eilrahC
,floWcaM boR si sihT
tsafkaerb yna wonK“ .deddon seluJ .dias eh ”,taht rof nwod eb d’I os ,yadot snalp on dah I ,lleW“ .gniggurhs ,delims eilrahC ”.yad rehtona uoy htiw yats ot tnaw tsomla I“
.keew a neve ebyam ,syad elpuoc a eraps dluoc I os
.ti hctam taebtraeh sih tlef eh tib elttil a retfa dna
reilrae yad a flah tuoba tem ylno dah eh nam a fo deb eht
.deddon eilrahC .deksa eh
.nruter on fo tniop a saw ti taht tcaf eht did ron
:ti draeh naht erom cisum eht tlef seluJ ereh tub
.deksa seluJ ”?yllaeR“
,kcezzoW rreH yb
,srats fo tol a tuo tolb dluow ti denigami eh tub
”,worromot neve ro ,yadot ti tuoba kniht ot evah t’nod uoY“
.delkcuhc neht eH
.eciov sih ot enot ygnos-gnis thgils a htiw deilper eh
.taeb eht htiw gnola bob ot gnitrats sredluohs sih ,sgniht esoht fo tsom gniod saw eh
”?KO ,yzarc oot og t’nod tsuJ
.ni emoc eilrahC gniees nopu feiler ni delahxe dna ,nwod dekool seluJ
.dias eh ”,oot ,llew yreV“
uoy ekil sdnuos ti em ot tuB“ .dias eh
.citegrene dekool ti timda ot dah eh dna ,tas eh erehw morf yaw eht lla taeh eht leef dluoc seluJ
”,kriK rof thgir tuoba sdnuos taht ,puY“ .seluJ dias ”,seY“
:elkcuhc ot nrut ’seluJ saw ti woN .gnihton gniyas
.thgin taht lausu naht retteb tpels dah eh rof ,rehtie ,eil a ton saw sihT
.dekniw tibbar ehT .deksa eh ”?kriK“
.skeehc sih
.niaga tey dellews traeh ’seluJ ,siht ta dnA
,gnitseretni eb t’now uoy yas uoY“
”!haohW“ .gnortsmrA seluJ saw taht niatnuom eht gniees nopu tuo deglub seye sih dna ,denrut kriK
.peels otni eilrahC dewollof eh sa yrrow siht tuoba togrof raeb eht neht dna ,smra sih ni derons anut eht tub ,esle gnihtyna detcepxe dah eilrahC fi derednow seluJ
.gnicreip eye eht ta pu dekool neht eilrahC
”,seert erom erew ereht hsiw I“ .deddon seluJ
.rab eht sdrawot seluJ dellup eilrahC ,siht htiw dnA
,deneppah taht revenehw seye fo noitom eht ,daeh eht fo tsiwt eht wenk eh
”.ti tnaw t’nod uoy fi nuf on ,puY“
,neppah dluow gnihtemos yllautneve tub ,lufrednow dna eerf tlef eh :dluow eh ,oN
.mih no ezag sih gnipeek syawla saw anut eht
”.era yeht woh wonk uoY
.ti gniees nopu delims seluJ dna ,elppin sih evoba tsuj gnitser daeh sih htiw elbaroda etiuq dekool anut ehT
eht ta taes a gnikat
”.sruoh ylbissop ,elihw a rof rood eht ta kcuts eb ll’ew ,etal ni teg ot yrt ew fI
”,syoB lateM“ ”?eno hcihW
.seye s’rehto hcae ni dekool yeht sa gniteem sezag rieht ,seluJ ta pu dekool eilrahC
”.yug gib ,kcab m’I ,thgirlA“
.sih htiw cnys ni spih sih evom ot nageb eilrahC taht deciton seluJ
,revewoh ,leef dluoc eh redduhs tnasaelp tsom eht saw tI
.ti tuoba thguoht eh nehw mih ot gnibrutsid neve ton saw