”.od ll’eilrahC“ zes sulla
,tiksib elats ,eeffoc daB
’lO	 :dab syawla si emit ’nidnarb zuC
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
saw sihT     ”.od ll’kcaJ“
.raef ot thguan ev’I kcaJ htiw wonk I tuB
pu ton s’nus ehT
,ekat ll’serahs rieht syob meht lla ’nA
,orevO ovitlA yb meop a ,”oD ll’kcaJ“
:yojne esaelP  .lysaeW no
,orevO ovitlA yb meop a uoy gnidaer m’I yadot dna
),7102 ,sserP lesaeW( II emulov
,raey ytnewt hgin rehtegot dekrow ev’eW
llitS	 ,niag ot esle thgua
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,re’o si evird gnol tsal eht nehw oS
”.od ll’eilrahC“ ,zes kcaJ
.niaga snaeb dloc ,srettups erifkooc ehT
.niar ot strats ti dna
,dam er’swoc dna ’nilwab er’sevlac nehW
,dah eb ot yap rof krow ot tog ev’ew dnA
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.yas ll’yeht tahw si ”!tsud ekil skool eH“
,erohs si yap eht ,dlos er’swoc mehT
”.od ll’eilrahC“ ,zes kcaJ
ekac ro tiksib hserf sekab eikooC nehW
tuB	 ”.yad rebmevoN krad a fo em sdnimeR“
,stsaeB deziliviC ni deraeppa tsrif hcihw
meop a ,”oD ll’kcaJ“
)yrteoP esroh-woC( oD ll’kcaJ  orevO ovitlA yb
:yarg a ekil t’nseod si ereht sklof emoS
”.od ll’eilrahC“ ,zes kcaJ
roF	 ,rood s’erutsaP lanretE eht ta dnats I ’nA
eH	 .raen s’eh wonk I dna em no stnuoc eH
,yas I redir a
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
’lO	 .ekats ta dnats I erehw emos em sgnirb kcaJ