,enalp sih fo enoceson eht gnola nur ot wap a desiar eH ".naretev
?woH" .remmats I "?...yhW"
.detnaw yeht tahw od em ekam ot yaw a dnuof yeht – si taht ,snamuh eht – edis ruO
.yaw taht pu deriw t'nera tsuj sevloW
.gniralf slirtson sih ,spsag drahcnerT  ".prahs yrev era hteet siH
".htob sevlowerew dna nem rof ,ecalp retteb a dlrow siht ekam ot yrt
.erac ot peed oot yaw ni m'I tub ,monev tnangidni htiw spird eciov siH
.redrosid sserts citamuart-tsop sa noitidnoc s’ekcleoB ezingocer ylbaborp d’ew ,yadoT
.yawa thgir dnopser t'nseod noraB ehT
.kool retteb a teg ot deen I
,siweL gniw-pot ym morf tsrub dnuor-xis a ffo tel I
.em morf yawa nac I sa drah sa meht gnilf dna
;xal ytterp teg ytiruces tel uoY
.rednuht delffum ,sselmrah a ni su dnuora dellor
?flow a thgif ot em gnidnes saw eh wonk drahcnerT diD
?nien ,sevlowerew eb dluoc sredael s'namuh eht fo lufdnah a ylno fI"
dedaerd eht htiw tabmoc yldaed ni dekcol s'eh won tub
,ruf ym gnilffur maertspils
enalp ruoy dnuof eW !daed erew uoy thguoht eW"
.drahcnerT ,ynnaryt on eb ll'erehT"
.susreV sevlowereW ni dna
,snommoC fo esuoH eht
.thgilrats ergaem eht ni ediw ,yawyna em ta pu gnihsalf seye sih fo setihw eht hctac I tub ,sdiar-ria eht tsniaga tuokcalb rednu s'nodnoL
.esoppus I ,ylreporp su draug ot sdleif srednalF ni daed nem gnuoy enif ynam oot
?I ma won ,dnammoc ruoy rednu yllautca ton m'I tpecxE"
,yawa pets rehtona ekat I
.ylivaeh shgis dna ,yks eht ta pu serats eH ".yrros
".repooC ,hO .ttoG rebeil ,hO .ho ...erofeb
.esolc yrev elzzum ym evom dna ,redluohs sih nopu wap a tup I
.gnidnenu smees ti ,tnecsed ruO
",lleW"  .ydnarb fo ksalf sih noraB eht ssot I
.shgual dna ,setatiseh neht dna ,tsehc yrruf sih ot wap a sehcaer eH  ".evorpmi did I
.nalp eht fo trap reven saw mih gnikoops ;knilb I
.yrtnuoc eht ssorca lla seitilicaF denmad ruoy ni gnittor neeb ev'ohw sevlowerew rehto dnasuoht ytriht tuoba dna thgirwniaW dna em eb ll'tI .oN"
.rednauqs tonnac I eno dna ,tfig a s'tI
,llew ,tub ,tsrif ta tolip roop ylralugnis a saw I
".regnissaG saw eman siH
...repooC ,uoy ksa em teL
.ksalf eht morf pis a ekat I
.mih no pu gnisolc elbuort on evah I ecno rof dna ,dnuora knab ot thgir drah kcits eht esae I
.’desserped‘ ,yllaretil :tkcürdeb  .6191 ni dednuof
nam ehT"  .sreilf wollef s'noraB eht fo eno dehctapsed tsuj dah flesym I
,dnuorg eht no senalp ymene fo nordauqs a deyortsed s'eH
.taht tuoba yrroS .seY .hA"  " –
.sruoy fo yrujni raw dlo taht ,ydaerla gnul a nwod er'uoy wonk I
.won evisneherppa ,htaerb prahs a ni skcus eH
,elbaccepmi otrehtih ,hsilgnE sih dna ,won retsaf elbmut sdrow s’noraB ehT  ”.did lla eW .sdneirf gnisol detrats I ,nwod deggob raw ehT .tsal t'ndid semit esoht tuB
.noitpeced yrassecen a saw ti tuB .keew retfa keew
,tnemom a rof tnelis s'eH
smret namreG fo yrassolG  2 fo
".ylimaf layor eht neve ,sdroL fo esuoH
,ssel on ,ydnarb yrrehC
taht htiw dna ,swap ym esaeler I
.yllaiciffo ton – saw reven I
,niaga knilb dna ,knilb I  ".sniw ydobyreve
.mih ekahs tonnac I ,lla timmad tub
,ssenkaew a ton dna htgnerts a si secnereffid ruo tuoba gniklat kniht ohw senO
,edis yb edis dednal
?eman s'nevaeh ni ,yhW
.taht mih evig ll'I ,ysllab s'eH
,mir s'tipkcoc eht revo wap a
".5ES ym retfa thgir ,retturts-eev s'noraB eht tnrub eW .llew sa enalp a nwod era snamreG eht ,noitalosnoc yna s'ti fI
.etfärktiertstfuL eht yllanif dna ,yrlavac eht neht dna ,nevele ta tedaC
/lardehna/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:ptth
,lardehnA yb
2 traP ,lardehnA yb
...em llet tsum uoY" .neht repsihw I
...ereht revo thgirwniaW
,trapa teef ytriht ton ,rehtona eno htiw kcol seye rebma fo sriap owT
.slauqe sa snaem eH"
enod era sehcnert eht ni sdos roop esoht fo lla hcum woh tsuj etamitserednu uoy kniht I .ton kniht I
”regeaJ“ fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
– namuh a ereh fo tuo klaw nac uoY .eruS"  "?eciohc A"
.ees uoy ,llew oot lla em wenk eH .aJ"  ".hA"
;tnereffid elttil a si yrots nwo yM"
.sdrow fo eciohc rooP .yrroS"
.diova rehtar hcum d'eh raw namuh a ni gnithgif otni decreoc
.rethguals dna dum htiw
.sevlow rof yllaicepse dewerb yteirav lohocla-wol eht neve s'ti dna
,yawa selim ytnewt spahrep ,egarrab gniogno na fo elbmur ehT
".ti dne ohw seno eht eb ot gniog era ew tuB
,irauR nosmirC yb
.erom sdnoces erom net tsuj rof demmaj yats sih fo snug nmad esoht taht nem dna sevlow fo sdog eht lla yb yarp I
.etteragic a rof gnioG ?taht eeS"
,ecroF riA namreG eht
.drahcnerT"  ma 11:2 7191 ,32 enuJ nodnoL
,flow rehto eht fo enihseye eht sehctac eh sa hctiwt ydob sih leef I dna ,moor eht ssorca kcilf seye siH
– wonk I kcirt yreve deirt ev'I dna ,od I wonk I
.yawyna revo selppot ti
.elzzum detniop ,gnoL
.ecnarF nrot-raw fo sdleif eht evoba hgih noraB deR
.sredael weN"  "?tahW"
.setunim ytriht ylluf rof decnad ev'eW
.eussi ot ecrof ot tsuj
.taht ekil no gniog tpek tsuj tI .ajaN" .hgis gniredduhs rehtona sevig eH
,yratilim dne-pot eht gnitegrat er'eW
.swalc fo egdun eht leef mih gnittel ,raluguj sih gnola sregnif ym fo skcab eht hsurb I
.won suoludercni ylreporp si drahcnerT  "...noraB deR ehT"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sredluohs flow daorb ym gurhs I ".ebyaM"
.tihS  .lla ta nam oN
eb t'now osla ew tuB
.diarfa m'I ,elbaliavanu ...yliraropmet er'yehT
.uoy rof emas eht od ot em rof emit
,ylneddus etiuq ,neht dnA
.llik eht rof tnemarepmet laer on tub ,reylf enif ,enif A
".yllagel ,aera yerg ytterp a saw taht yas d'I ,flow a s'eh taht won tuB .esac tnereffid a eb thgim eh ,llew
.wonk uoy erus m'I
.secivres eht rof syawla saw I
.gnireffo m'I si ti tahw dootsrednu t'nsah eH .gnirats
.hO"  "?ytilicaf siht gnidraug eb ot desoppus era ohw sPM nezod-flah eht tuoba ksa ot evah neve I oD"
,ris ,uoy erussa I
,ecnarF ni gniyd llits era nemria hsitirB ynam os yhw snosaer eht fo eno s'ti ;tcaf fo tniop ni ,erawa yletucA .od I ,seY .seY"
.nwonk evah nac eh kniht t'nod I"
"...hgrrru..."  .deb eht ot ylmrif tsehc sih nip ot rehto eht esu dna htuom sih ssorca wap eno pmalc I yawa mriuqs ot seirt eh sA
,enecs cillydi ylesrevrep a saw dewollof tahW
srae ym leef dna
.niaga esra ym htaenrednu pu thgir s'eH
.eromyna uoy rof sdnarre yna gninnur eb t'now I taht dnatsrednu esaelp ,esac hcihw ni
".won thgir ,ereh thgir
,esruoc fo tub – boj eht rof flow thgir eht dnif dluoc eh ylno fi
.ylper I nehw eciov ym ni elims eht peek I os dnA
.nam eht ta kool tneced-flah a teg ot dah ev'I ecnahc tsrif eht ,regral reve gniworg
.dnuorg eht ot nwod yaw eht lla taht ekil llaf mih dehctaw I dna ,gnimaercs ydaerla ,gninrub ydaerla ,tuo deliab eh
,yllaer dna ,mih edisgnola teg ot deen I lla si thgie tuo snruT
.rood eht tsniaga ylteiuq gninael yltnerruc s'ohw
– yks eht fo modeerf eht ,deeps fo hsur ehT .tsrif ta gniticxe ytterp lla saw tI"
"?ereht revo ,ti saw thgirwniaW ...dna uoy tsuj ,tahW"
.raw siht trats t'ndid sevlowereW"
.hcnuah ym tsniaga mrif ylgnirussaer raeg-gnidnal eht fo sturts eht
,teiuq ytterp ti tpek sroirepus yM
,enalp ym no kcab nael dna knilb I   ".ma I
.tnelis era snug sih
.yawyna sdnoces wef a rof
.dias uoy tahw si" ,tsal ta srettum eh ",'gnitegraT'"
"...emit eht ,emit ehT" .em ta slworg thgirwniaW ",repooC"
".nwod resiaK eht morF .ynamreG ni ssorca ,tnemom siht ta thgir
".eromyna ton – desu
RAOR ni deraeppa evah seirots trohs esohw retirw dna naicisum a
.drahcnerT ,uoy mrah ot ereh t'nsaw I dias I nehw ti tnaem I"
".tnaem uoy tahw si 'gnitanissassa' tuB
:etfärktiertstfuL  .nordauqs rethgif namreG a
:teiuq yrev dna ,yllautneve tuB
".reh nrub ot emahs elbirret A
,thginot eciohc a uoy gnireffo m'I
,ecnalab no tuB .ylbissoP"
.waj sih stes drahcnerT
".drah eid syaw namuh eht fo emoS
.raw eht trats t'ndid sevlowereW
.ecaf yrruf a pota srae dekaep-tfos ,egraL
.em morf yawa teg ot gniyrt tuoba kniht neve t'nod dnA
.uoy truh annog toN
.yletunim daeh sih gnikahs ,em ta stniuqs eH
:tuo nar leuf ruo erofeb tfarc ruo nwod tes ot tops teiuq a dnuof d'ew ,hguone ylgnizamA
.ytiniffaruf.www//:ptth ta dnuof eb nac krow sih fo tsoM
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.rehtegot ,flow dna flow sA
.ssim ot em rof elbissop yldrah s'tI
.stsuahxe gnilooc fo knit ,knit eltneg eht ot sdneirf dlo ekil seirots gnippaws
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ettelap denifer a sah noraB ehT
eht ni pu ,eb dluoc sevlow doog woh draeh d'eh esoppus I
.demmaj evah snug siH
.erofeb keew eht tsuj ,gniddew sih ta hceeps a nevig d'I
.yrtnafni ydoolb roop eht lla sa gnittel-doolb eht fo kcis sa tsuj era ohw seno
.seye nedlog gninihs fo riap a ot tsol gnol ydaerla saw I noitamrofsnart ym fo emit eht yb ,esruoc fo tub
.ylper ni kcab sdon neht ,tnemom a tub rof setatiseh eH  .dnaL
.yas t’ndluoc I ,stsal ti gnol woh ;su neewteb sllaf ecneliS
.sffocs eh dna ,slruc pil siH .mih rof hcum oot tsuj s'tahT
:leffatsdgaJ ro ,atsaJ
.gnirrulb saw ti – sdlrow namuh dna flow eht fo noitarapes naelc ehT
",dellik tsuj I taht
.htimS niatnuoM eht
ot pu s'noraB deR eht tahw htiw etanidro-oc ot dnA"
.lla ta gnirvueonam ton s'eh ,tcaf nI
".llew sa ereht revo dneirf ym enola tel ,em ekat t'ndluoc uoy wonk uoY
.trats eht morf gniklat eht eldnah thgirwniaW tel evah dluohs I spahreP
.flow a emaceb I erofeb neve ,nam yratilim a saw reven I"
;ysetruoc htiw em detaert syawla ev'uoY
".gnissim ylsuoiretsym era smraedis rieht lla taht dnif ll'yeht pu ekaw yeht nehw tub ,demrahnu er'yeht ,yrrow t'noD
”?s5ES fo era ew trohs woh aedi yna evah uoy oD
.snug sih fo eldnah gnigrahc eht gnikrow yllacitnarf ,seenk sih neewteb kcits ,tipkcoc eht ni gnidnats s'eh ,oN
.mih morf kcab pets a ekat I ".sdrow
– ssorca emoc reve ev'I tolip ydoolb tseb eht redrum ot tuoba m'I
hcaer I .nwad lufdaerd dna elab taht ni sdleif dehcnerd-doolb eht evoba hgih
– kniht I ,t'ndid yeht em rof toN
.tih laturb a sekat turts-gniw trop yM
,gniklat erom ,gnithgif sseL
.skeew trohs eerht fo naps a ni nemria deillA fo erocs a dellik dah em morf ssorca tsuj gnittis flow ehT
.erofeb ...mih wenk uoY .hA"
".dlo sraey eno-ytnewt saw eH
?thgir ,gnimaercs eht tuoba dias ew tahw rebmemer tsuj os ,won yawa swap ym ekat ot gnioG .ho-
,drahcnerT ,oS .thgiR .hO"
ecar smra wen-dnarb a
.kcits eht fo hctiwt tnemom-tsal a yb noisilloc a gnidiova ylno ,mih toohsrevo I ,debmuneB
.pots t'nod tsuj yeht trats yeht ecno dna ,sraet eht kcab dloh t'nac I
.dias evah dluohs I ,sey ,hO
.hcum taht lla truh t'now ti
.em ot ssorca ti sessot neht ,ksalf-pih revlis elttil a morf giws a sekat eH
.esolc yllaer
,sidlA eht fo scitpo eht ni secnad ydob s'reylf ehT
,tolip delliks a dna oreh-flowerew ruo
ecaf sih evoba esolc gnimool mrof hsiflow ym ot noitcaer siH  "!HHGRAA – hhaarrru..."  ".nam ,pu ekaW .drahcnerT"  "...rrrrru..."  ".drahcnerT"
.uoy llik annog toN"
rehtona ro yaw eno – revewoH
;regeilF red ruednammoK rof noitaiverbba :lfoK
,ees uoy ,lfoK eht tuB .sreylf namuh eht fo yna etib ot denilced ,sevlesmeht krow eht od ot denilceD
.htaed sseltniop ,diputs a
.hcrib dna hceeb fo sespoc esned yb sedis eerht no dednuorrus ,hguone level dna htooms tub ,dleif hsillams a
.redisnoc mih gnittel
.naretev a er'uoy ,did eh ekil thgie-ytnewt ot teg uoy fi ,syad eseht
,senihcam evitcepser rieht fo sleehw eht tsniaga kcab gninael
.noitisoporp a htiw ,yad eno em ot emac ruednammoK eht neht tuB .tib a depleh satsaJ eht desinagro I yaw eht esoppus I hguohtla – ti ot dne yna ees dluoc su fo enoN
,peehs tnediser eht rettacs ot ssap wol a edam eW
;teef dnasuoht eerht ta tih a koot knat leuf s'remmihcS yad txeN
.flow a mrah ,reve ,reveN
,uoy htiw krow rehtar hcum d'I tuB
.ssorca ecnalg ot senilced dna tleb deef eht htiw gnissem llits s'eh tub ,em raeh nac eh taht tbuod on s’erehT
,ti fo retteb skniht ,niaga ksalf eht krocnu ot fi sa sekam eH
ythgiR"  .sdon eh ,yllautnevE
ereh dnA .raw eht dne pleh ot ,gnihtyna – flow a sa neve ,gnithgif no yrrac d'I wenk eH
.sreggirt eht morf pils sbmuht yM
".slanesra rojam eht lla dna ,spihs latipac eht lla fo egrahc gnikat osla er'ew ,sediseb dna ,hO
.shguob gnidaerps eht htaeneb thgis fo tuo senalp eht deleehw dna
,dias eh ,raw eht netrohs thgim tI .wolb evisiced a rof ,ytiroirepus ria rof ecnahc a saw ereht thguoht eh ;ria
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.gnorw neeb dah lfoK s'noraB ehT
.spil sih epiw ot eugnot flow gnol sih tuo gnittup neht dna ,gnippis ,no seog eh
.ebyaM"  ".raw livic si"
.buc ruo dnA .etam ym denetaerht yehT
.meht ot denruter nem gnuoy rieht fo emos tsael ta ekil dluow eporuE ssorca segalliv dna snwot ynam woH
?enalp nwo ruoy tnrub uoY"
?ekat lrig roop ym nac tnemhsinup erom hcum woH
,dnuora kcab elcric ot trats I sa ,neht dnA
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.dnuorg eht ta regnif a baj dna
,dehsarc eh nehw ni daeh sih dehsab ,ria-dim tfarc yldneirf a deppilC .yawyna gniylf tpek eH .tkcürdeb …os ,tuo gnurw os tog eh tub ,su fo tseb eht saw eH .og ekcleoB was I“  .yresim cinotueT krad a htiw golc ot strats
,elbanosaernu ton si
.noraB eht ekahs tonnac I
,repooC tfel ew emit tsaL
"!aH"  "?yratilim eht ni neeb uoy evah gnol woh
.nrael stolip rehto eht ees ot devol eh dna ,drow hsrah a reven ,nam derepmet-teews A"
"?uoy etib ot flow rehtona dnif uoy did ...uoy diD
.ylisaenu stfihs flow rehto ehT ".hO"  "?eh saw ohw
uoy rof daer eb osla lliw yrots s’yadoT
".siht lla nalp ot ,kniht d'uoy naht drawrofthgiarts erom yllautca saw tI
,talf llaf srae ym leef I .srulb noisiv yM
".esolc taht tog yllaer reve seips s'drahcnerT kniht t'nod ew
",siht ekil neeb ylno ev'I
.mu ,dna ,gniylf ta doog tsuj saw I
*******  ?wonk drahcnerT diD
.yrros ma I !eßiehcS"  ".buc
”regeaJ“   yojne esaelP
.ekahs ydob ym leef I
.scitna yna gnivah eb t'nac I tub
.detarepsaxe ,pu sepip thgirwniaW yllautnevE
,edis ym yb gniyl selggog eht rof leef I
.ti gnidne eb dluow ew –
.trap tnatropmi erom eht si yhw eht ,spahrep ,kniht I"
– tcepsersid on – dna
.gnilbmert morf swap ym pots t'nac I
.won skeew eerht revo tsuj ,ho
.kcat tnereffid a yrt ot gnidiced erofeb
.ereht ecalos llams emos dnif thgim eh fi sa
– su fo seno redlo eht fo eno yllautca saw eH .wollef rooP"
.regna dna tnemelzzup ot cinap morf stfihs tnecs s'drahcnerT ,ylwolS
.sreggirt eht ot sbmuhT
,tnorf wen a pu denepo tsuj d'eH .lla ta raw eht denetrohs t'ndah eH
.sreviuq elzzum siH
srotaiva-flow wollef owt tsuj
".gniht eht s'ereh
,lardehnA yb
,llahetihW  *******  .pu ylwols emoc
.on dias lla dah sevlow namreG eht
,klat ot deen eW ?dnatsrednu uoY
?noitinumma fo tuo nur reven suadnapS esoht lliW
;nwod ti tes ot seirt dna
.sproC gniylF layoR eht fo rednammoc sa drahcnerT hguH fo tnelaviuqe namreG eht yllacisab
"...mures fo hsats terces siht fo dloh nettog d'eh
– doolb s'rotcurtsni daed ym htiw deraems llits
...llew gniog ton era sgnihT
”regeaJ“ fo strap owt fo dnoces eht eht saw sihT
.egde gnittuc lahtel sti ta dna ni dekcus sevlow htiw
,slrans eh ",teg ll'uoy tahW"
.ytilibissop dna tbuod htiw dereyal ylhcir si tnecs siH
,tnelis si drahcnerT
"!degnah uoy htiw pu dniw ylbaborp ll'taht laitram-truoc ytsan yrev a ta gnikool er’uoy won thgir tub ,gniod er'uoy kniht uoy tahw wonk t'nod I ,repooC"  .slrans dna hteet sih stirg drahcnerT
,pu mih stuhs tahT
".dnatsrednu uoy fi doN ?ti toG
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer
.gnimaercs yna tnaw t'nod I dna ,won dna
,rof' ,yerg dna nat delttom fo tlep sih ot gnirutseg ,syas noraB eht
,enalp retteb eht evah I