.rettam eht ni eciohc tsethgils eht ton evah I gniwonk
:sarrA fo tsae selim neetxis ,iauoD
,ecnednopserroc hguorht krow lagelarap gniod yb rood eht morf flow eht tpek I
,txen od ot ylekil er'yeht tahw ot sa sseug tseb ym ekam
– sgnivas 'stnerap ym fo tsom hguorht netae dah hcihw gniniart
.em etib ot reh dedausrep yllanif I erofeb htnomevlewt lluf a saw tI
.don truc a mih gnivig ,llat pu srae ym krep dna sgnaf ym edih od I ,'ris' mih llac t'now llits I hguohtlA
,drahcnerT hguH riS lareneG-reidagirB si siht roF
:flesym pots etiuq t'nac I tub
– erofeb 5ES na thguof reven ev'yeht taht em sekirts tI
,duol dna dliw yarb aziuS-onapsiH eht fo sesroh derdnuh owt ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.evoba dna em erofeb elbmut dna weps sgnisac tneps eht ,elzzum ym ni snrub ekoms etidroc
.won thgir fo tuo gniylf si sucriC eht erehw s'taht
– sevlow ot ton ,snamuh ot rettam sknar yratilim yllis esoht dna doohthgink eht – eltit nitulafhgih sih tuoba tihs a evig t'nod I
.nees reve dah I taht erutaerc lufituaeb tsom eht saw ehS
.emoc ev'I yaw eht kcab eltruh dna spitgniw reh no revo tfarc ym worht I neht dna
.evah dluoc flow a dneirf namuh tseB
”regeaJ“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht eht saw sihT     .ylF
tops eht ot detoor ereht doots s'ohw ,etanidrobus sih ot kcab snrut eh
".oga ruoh na flah a tsuj ,sthgil s'regnah eht yb flesym ti detsujdA
,stnet eht tuo kcip seye flow ym teef derdnuh a morf
,yerg dillap ekilduorhs eht ni bmilc dnilb fo erom sdnoces neetfiF
.eno siht ton ,'gnihtemos' a toN
.niur yreif ni ezalb senalpib nezod A
;erew ew naht redlo yna ylecracs saw
.epod dna tirips muelortep enatco-hgih fo gnat tnatsid eht htiw elzzum ym ni delgnim tnecs yef reH
.htaeh-rehtaeh yerruS fo aes a dima
.smaj yna evah t'ndluohs uoy
,emordorea sproC gniylF layoR
,tilps evisnefed a ekam yeht os ,egatnavda thgieh eht evah I dna deepsria eht evah I
,selggiuqs dna sedoc elttil ytterp ynam os ot decuder sdnasuoht fo snet eht yb nem
,erew ew ereht os dnA
.nwo ym fo rebma eht htiw seye nworb sih hctac nac I resolc s'eh taht won ;srae ym kcilf I ".evah
.retemitla eht orez
".em etib ot uoy ksa d'I spahrep"
.ti ot pu t'nsi yllaer thgiseye rieht
;dekcehc neeb s'dnuor yreve ,ffo deppot s’noitinummA .pu delleuf llA"
.revocer ot tseb sih seod dna sleeh sih skcilc yllautca toidi ehT "!ris-
tiB' .roolf teuqrap eht sehsurb
:ecnetsixe-oc ,elbats yltnerappa tub ,ysaenu na neeb dah tluser ehT
1 traP ,lardehnA yb
– gniniart s'reywal ym fo lla rednauqs ot denimreted dna emoc yeht sa decaf-hserf dna evïan sa ,saw I owt-ytnewT
,reggib ,sevlow eht dna
.em ta pu secnalg dna ,tep devol-llew a erew enigne eht fi sa dlofinam eht stap nam ehT .eson eht dnuora morf segreme thgirwniaW fo mrof ywodahs ehT
su gnoma flow ylno eht dna – su fo tseb ehT
;gnirvueonam suoires rof wol oot yaw m'I
,em evigrof flesreh floW-ykS taerG eht yam dnA
,cirbaf dna eriw fo seergilif ysmilf naht erom elttil erew sgniht ylniagnu eht
.ees nac I taht sduolc tsekciht eht rof mia dna
.deeps ni egde elbaredisnoc a tog s'ehs tub ,tfarc namreG eht sa eliga sa etiuq eb ton yam drib yM
.eriw leets tuat dna cirbaf depod ni etanracni edam regnirb-htaed a
.snamuh fo sriaffa eht fo lla diovA
?ssap ot emoc thgim tahw yas dluoc ohW
.eganrac fo yhpargoerohc eht
,hcnert no hcnert fo sgaz-giz eht
.lla ta em fo deracs llems t'nseod eH
,cit tnetsisrep a deriuqca yltnecer sah eye thgir siH
.gnis ot strats dribkcalb a ,regnah eht yb revO
,evah stnemelttes esoht fo emos
,gnikahs pots t'now sdnah sih sgninrom emos
;kcab selbmuts dna spsag eH
.tnorf eht dnuora lla sdleifria tnereffid neewteb gnitfihs
gnieb emit eht rof dna
.tnorf pu thgir porp dedalb-owt 'lo giB .tsaeb a
,072 si etacifitrec s'rotaiva sih fo rebmun laires ehT
,gnillik rieht od ot llew em deniart ,em deniart
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer
.ti ot hcihw htiw CFR eht ni etarc nmad tseb eht em nevig ev'yeht tsael tA
:sPM owt eht ot ,neht dnA
,syad ylrae esoht ni no nrael ot su evag yeht tahw erew senalpib-rehsuP
gnitaidar llits taeh eht leef nac I srekciV eht morf teef owt doog a gnidnatS .dah eH
– tiftuo sih gnillac er'yeht tahw si sucriC gniylF s'nefohthciR noV" .ylmirg ,sffuh drahcnerT ".wobniar
/lardehna/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:ptth ta dnuof eb nac
.od nac I taht tol a ton s'ereht ,llew – thgir taht tog t'nevah ssarb pot eht fI
,gnurts-hgih smees ehs nwad eht erofeb ruoh na wolg nretsae tniaf eht nI
;dehctaw dna kcab tas sevlow elihw ,tuo gnideelb saw ytinamuH
.repooC" .eye ym teem etiuq t'now eH
".eceip eno ni kcab etarc eht gnirb ot yrt esaelp dnA"
,regnorts ,rekciuq
,egrevnoc srecart eht ytilibativeni gnillappa na htiw sa
,kcits eht no kcab llup I .hguone s'taht
;smihw rieht ot dlrow eht gnidneb reverof sregnif dna sdnim elbmin htiw seno eht
.tnemom eht fo doom eht nethgil ot gnihtemos tsuj
..."   ?lla ta ffo ekat ot evah toidi eht did yhW
*******  .dne na ot ti wenk ew sa dlrow eht gnignirb ni trap a deyalp ohw rotarran roop siht saw ti
.flesti ssendlim si drahcnerT
– gnol tiaw t'nac I tub ,ylluferac mih hctaw I
.reddur ot rotaidar morf hctip sa kcalb detniap ,enalpiB
.llabruf nmad uoy ,ereht pu erac ekat uoY"
.dniheb kool lanif a ekat I dleihsdniw ym sgof ruopav eht erofeb tsuj dna ,sulumuc yhctap emos tih ot trats I teef dnasuoht a tA
.sderhs ot snordauqs ruo gniraet era senalp sih dna
.dniheb sdray ytfif ebyam sretturts-eev owt tub eno ton gnispmilg ,dnuora daeh ym enarc I trop ot yldliw wels ew sa dna
.nwo ym ton s'taht doolb htiw stam elzzum yM
.ruf dna sgnaf eht ekat ot noisiced ym detterger ecno reven dah ,flow duorp a neeb syawla d'I  .secivres
...lanoisacco emos redner ylno dluow flow-tolip niatrec a ,nruter ni
.noitcerid thgir eht ni gnikool er'yeht fi ,em fo espmilg a teg ot srennug tfarcria-itna rieht rof hguone thgiL
,sduolc eht ni erehwemos dediser luos reH
.thgir ot neht dna tfel ot tsrif ,sih fo tfarc elttil elbmin taht knij ot strats dna ereht m'I swonk tolip eht ;thgis sidlA eht ni tohs eht pu gninil ,eulb-dna-neerg rof pmulp I .meht fo eno wollof ylno nac I
.repooC ,gniht eht s'ereH"
enihcam uadnapS niwt fo rettahc otaccats kciuq eht ,'kat-kat-kat' railimaf oot lla taht s'ereht ylneddus dna
.mih eb dluow ti dnuorg eht ffo teg ot gniog saw enoyna fi esruoc fo dna ,noraB deR eht
.emit eht lla gninethgirb si yks eht ;ecnahc a ylniatrec s'erehT
– yporhtnasim fo llac neris eht detsiser syawla d'I
S"  ".tseug ruo feirb ot sa doog os eb esaelP
,sproC gniylF layoR eht fo rednammoC ehT
".ekil yllaer s'gniylf tahw ees ll'uoy woN"
,degnahc ydob ym sa yltneg em dleh ehS
;htaed fo nid a ni nekawa snug ehT
niuqelrah dlob a ni detniap si enalp s'noinapmoc siH
".nefohthciR nov derfnaM
.sraet lufyoj ot yldipar em gnirb dluoc rethgual reh dna
.thgir eman sih gnitteg fo ysetruoc eht noraB doog eht od tsael ta s'tel ;niatpaC ,nefohthciR noV"  "– nevahthciR nov derfnaM fo eman ,yltnerappa noraB emoS
,drawrof repmacs stellub ym neht tuB
.gnilwoc s'tipkcoc eht nopu tsif yrruf a nwod gnimmals ,maercs I ,"!KCUF"
,kciots tub tnatculer
.gniht thgir eht dias ev'I wonk I ,gnihsalf seye ,em ta kcab snirg eh nehW
"– esolc lufwa si sdray ytriht yas llits I ,repooC"
".htfif yreve recart ,omma dradnats ,srekciV ehT .seiraidnecni sah pot pu nug siweL ehT
,hctaw I ,hctaw I dnA
sepirts s'niatpac a gniraew nam gnidlab ,ylesaew a laever ot nepo sgniws rood ehT
.evid wollahs a otni enalp ym egdun dna ,hgis I
– duolc eht fo mottob eht fo tuo hcnup I
.tuo tniop ot luferac erew yeht ,sevlowerew rof dlrow suoregnad a emoceb dah tI
nodyorC eht ni sevlowerew rehto dnasuoht owt htiw rehtegot lla I dna naipsaC gnuoy dna aivlyS
...dnah rehto eht no ,sevlowereW
,sdnopser enalp yM
,knat leuf eht ezirusserp
.snif gnilooc s'lerrab eht ffo
”regeaJ“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT
.tsahga yletairporppa gnikool dna
.snopaew ym htob morf tsrub dnoces-owt
,ytilicaF eporhtnacyL
.sdnah thgir eht ni ton – ksat reh morf krihs reven lliw ehS  .redrum enrobria
.esolc s'eh ;duol era snug siH
.gniw rewol draobrats ym ssorca sraeppa seloh dnuor taen fo rettaps a ,knilb a nI
:etuloser erew snoitan lla fo sevlow ehT
.raef dna niadsid htiw yvaeh si tnecs siH
.sragic dna sgol kao fo ekoms elats eht htiw nialrevo
.noitcartsid ot reh evol I dna ,ylgu fo tros ym s'ehs tub ,eb yam ehs ylgU
.flow a mrah – reve – reven dnA
".won og nac uoY .nemeltneg ,uoy knahT"
”regeaJ“   yojne esaelP
.gnikam rieht fo reven saw taht ytinasni na htiw kcurt on evah dluow yeht
.sdneirf ym tsgnoma snamuh fo ytnelp detnuoc llits I ,os nevE
.taorht sih sraelc 'gnihtemos‘ sihT ".hA"
,sraw-lla-dne-ot-raw eht llac retal dluow nem tahw fo tsdim eht ni
,dnah nwo sih ni mraerof yrruf ym sekat eh daetsnI
.ssenerawa laitaps dna sexelfer s'flowerew a htiw tolip yna reven dna
,emitefil tnereffid a nI"
*******  "!tcatnoC"  ".raelC"  "?raelC"
.noitnetta ot yltrams pans em knalf ohw nemecilop yratilim owt eht dna ,snrut eldnah eht retal tnemom a
,thgir lla nefohthciR s'taht ;boj-
.reh dnuora nekciuq ot smees ria yrev ehT
.esproc derrahc a morf seveirter eh
,yad eno taht tpecxe – raw ym fo yrots eht neeb evah llew thgim taht dnA
;sdray derdnuh eerhT
.erutseg eht pu kcip t'nod ylbaborp seye namuh sih ssenkrad eht ni ereh hguohta ,mih ta daeh ym ekahs I ".on ,oN"
.nips a otni nwod seson dna
.egrahc elbarenluv ,sselpleh a hcus htiw eno ,flow elamef gnuoy a rof emit suoregnad yllaicepse na saw ti dnA
.secneuqesnoc detcepxenu sti dna
.selggog ym no llup I
.55:4 daer kcolc tipkcoc eht fo sdnah suonimul ehT
.gnifeirb eht revo sekat drahcnerT sa nirg tub pleh t'nac I
;eciov sih ot elbmert etunim a s'erehT ".llabruf
,sllaw dellenap-krad
.raw ot denrut dah dlrow namuh eht fo hcum ,raey emas taht fo yluJ yB
".flow doog a rof edam evah d'uoy
,egelivirp ot nrob
.yerp sti gniltnam rotpar suortsnom emos ekil em evoba tuo hcaer sgniw reppu eht ,thgir dna tfel oT
.tohstoh wen dnarb a flesmih dnuof dna enog s'resiaK ehT" .gniniadsid ,sffins dna eson sih pu snrut gnihtemoS niatpaC
.ereht s'ti tub ,pu ti kcip t'ndluow regnarts a
–  – ssap tsal eno rof dnuora llup I .og ot emit s'tI
,lardehnA yb
.rae ym gnilzzun ,em ot derumrum ehs ",woN"
.yks eht rof serutaerc ylmeesnu
.steehsdaorb eht morf yletaidemmi esingocer I taht ehcatsuom demmirt-esolc kramedart taht gnitrops dna nrets dna tnuag
.egde repeed ,rehsrah a no sekat ,daol rednu gnimoc ,enigne eht dna
ev'yehT
"– reh teg nac I sa yadot doog sa s'ehs ,ydaer lla s'ehS"
:slobmys yratilim fo shpylgoreih deruoloc eht ,nialrevO
.selggog epiW .kcitS .elttorhT
,thgirwniaW leinaD
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.livic eb lla nac ew taht erus m'I
.niaga teem reven ll'ew ecnahc laer yrev a s'ereht
.esac siht ni ,swap thgir eht ni rO
tniap nosmirc thgirb a strops sortablA dael eht taht dnif ot desirprus yleritne ton m'I
.ylf dna derhs ,retnilps doowylp eht ees I
;sdaor dna sdleif
.tey snordauqs eht ot tuo neve ton
krow sih fo tsoM
.ksa ot thguoht neve meht fo enoN
.enim sa mrif sa tib yreve si dloh sih dna
,raw fo ytlausac erom eno tsuJ
.sucof wen thgirb a otni deredduhs dlrow ym sa sgnihton teews derepsihw
.ecneciter hsilgnE cissalc taht ,gnippord sredluohs ,tnemom a rof setatiseh eH "...llew ,haeY"
.woleb llew era senalp rehto ehT
.sevil rieht etacilpmoc ot ekil snamuh hcihw htiw seitilagel thguarf eht gnitagivan ylluferac
elaselohw fo noitucesorp eht
.em rof tuo gnikool syawla ,leinaD ,nam doog a er'uoY"
,tinu gnillik elibom ylhgih fo tros a otni ti denrut
flow derruf-yerg ,delcsum fo xis-toof-xis ot esolc siht eb ot dezafnu smees nam eht ,tiderc sih oT
.esromer ro noitanimircer rof emit on evah I .sseug ym yb ,sdray ytrihT
,kcatta fo elgna dna way fo yrteop eht ,gard dna tfil fo scisab eht ni su dellird eh sa ssarg eht no deggel-ssorc ereht tis d'eW
".no tops si ytrihT .esolc teg attoG"
"!rellik deniart a s'eh ,ereh repooC" .retsulf-a lla si gnihtemoS niatpaC "!ris ,tuB"
.yad rieht ot trats dab yrev a meht evig ot tuoba m'I
.em tpecretni ot dnuora kcab gnilcric si dneirf sih
"?snug eht no ecnegrevnoC"
ffot notE na fo ria elbakatsimnu eht dna
,hguone erus dna ,nwod ecnalg I
.mih evah ot flow ykcul a m'I
.raey a nihtiw sesnes sti ot nruter dluow ytinamuh
,5ES siht ,ledom wen dnarb a s'tI
.yawyna me' devol eW
,sdrow sih gniveileb etiuq ton ,mih ta kcab knilb I
*******  .yad taht litnu pu thgiR
?wollof ot hguone llew ,tuo em ekam yeht naC
,emarf regral s'flowerew a tius ot deifidom ylivaeh neeb s'taht tipkcoc a otni rebmalc I
,7191 nI  .dlog fo erul eht fo gniracnu ylemerpus dna foola yllausac ,dalc-ruf dna deit-erutan
.thgieh deen I dna ,ecnatsid deen I
.hcnilf t'nseod eh tub ,mih hsurc dluoc pirg ym llew lluf swonk eH
,regnissaG tneitap ,raed ,rotcurtsni ruO
,sllats neht dna – pu ylprahs sllup enalp neerg-eulb ytterp siH
.evol I drib a fo tipkcoc eht eb ot thguo ti ,tipkcoc a edisni eid ot gniog m'I fI
ssarg talf fo feihcrekdnah-tekcop a dleifria eht
a mih evig dna ,noitcelfed eht egduj ,sdray ytriht ot esolc I  ...thgir ti emit I fI .elbatciderp oot elttil a tsuj s'ti ,gniknij sih tuB .namria enif nmad a si tegrat yM
.yks eht ni recnad a dna ,etlevs dna teews saw aivlyS
– yhw yltcaxe dnatsrednu ot noitisop doog a ni m'I kniht I dnA .od ew tuB
,gnaf fo hsalf a dna eralg kciuq a mih evig I
,net-eno stih deepsria ehT
.gniyerg dna denil ydaerla tey seitriht sih ni ylno llits
.gnikil ym rof yelbeW sih fo draug-reggirt eht ot esolc oot rehtegotla s'taht regnif yhctiwt a sah tfel ym no eno ehT
;niatpaC ,won thgir ereh dedeen ton era sgod-draug s'ymra ehT"
.CFR eht ni rettif-cinahcem tseb eht llits s'eh ,nees s'eh taht srorroh eht lla etipsed tuB
:hturt nekopsnu eht wonk htob ew tuB
.sih fo eciohc on ,sdnah namuh yb yaw taht emaceb ylno eh tuB .si eh ,seY .seY"
7191 ,22 lirpA dnalgnE
.kcits eht no drawraer skrej eh msaps lanif sih ni dna
.sraey rednet neetenin emos fo elamef derruf-nat a saw –
tuhs skcilc rood eht sA
,suoregnad sleef enalp ym sialaC-ed-saP eht fo erutsap hsul eht no ylteiuq ereh gnittis tsuj nevE .selkcirp ruf yM
.kram rerus a dnif dna
.hcnert a ni ytrid stoob sih teg ot gniog reven s'ohw ffats-eht-no-gnihtemos pu-depmuj rehtona tsuj
;esroh derdnuh owt tuo gnihsup
;tfarcria rof sesucxe suolucidir
.flow a htiw yllanosrep teem ot emoc
.4191 fo hcraM ni nrob saw ,buc ruo ,naipsaC
pit yhsub sti litnu kcals gnah liat ym leef dna ,hgis I
.kat-kat-kaT  "...kcuf..."
,selgna drawkwa dna ssenixob lla ,enalp ylgu na si 5ES eht uoy llet lliw nemria emoS
.der htiw hsalps yltpurba selggog ym dna dleihsdniw yM
.enog dna dessap ydaerla s'tnemom eht tub
.ecaf ym ssorca taeh fo hsaw a s'ereht dna ,pu swolb ylneddus stnet eht fo eno edisni elbammalf yrev gnihtemoS
.ediw nepo elttorht eht mals dna tuo level I
.rehto eht ro edis eno yb derif sllehs evisolpxe hgih sseltnuoc yb detaretilbo neeb ,wonk I
.em fo sekil eht ni gnillac er'yeht fi etarepsed eb tsum yehT
,tnalprewop a rof 8V aziuS-onapsiH dekaewt A
.sevres yromem fi
,5191 ni no etal
.derae-god srenroc dna gnilruc segde sti ,ereht tuo deyalps s'taht pam eht ot revo elbma I os dnA
,dnim ym ni senalp namreG fo snoitisop tsal eht xif I
.rof deksa uoy ekil tsuj ,sdray ytrihT"
,seno ekilraw ,revelc eht
.em ees ot emac 5IM morf sguht derih fo essop elttil a
,ylteiuq tuo strulb eh ",emitefil tnereffid a nI"
.slive owt fo ressel eht raf yb saw ti seye rieht nI
.drahcnerT t'nsi moor eht ni ylteiuq gnitiaw nosrep rehto eht fi em nmad esuaceb – desirprus eb ot nrut ym s'ti ,txen tuB
ma 83:4 7191 ,52 lirpA
?thgirwniaW ekil snamuh erom eb ereht t'nac yhw ,timmaD ".lliw I"
.elbat eht tsniaga depporp s'taht kcits-reggaws nedoow ycnaf a rof sehcaer eH
.nwo ym fo eno sa mih kram cinut sih fo neerg-evilo eht ot nwes sgniw eht tub
.llew sa tsuj ylbaborP
,deniart ecyoR-slloR dna nrob erihskroY
,saw I sa dednuorg ylmrif
;liat eht dna tipkcoc eht neewteb emoh tih sdnuor tsrif yM
,tipkcoc a morf sesae eh tolip pu-tohs yreve htiw erom elttil a gniyd
,tih s'eh sa sdrawkcab dna pu stloj ydob s'reylf ehT
ecnarF nrehtron ,sarrA CFR  *******  ".sderhs
.yldneirfnu ton tub mrif si nruter ni teg I elims ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,hsilop doow fo keer tnegnup a :won ,stnecs hserF
.flow a saw I wonk ot dedeen stneilc ym fo enoN
.secnef eriw-debrab hgih dna syek dna skcol fo seitingidni eht reffus ot ydaer
– rettel s'tnerap gnivol a spahrep ,esac etteragic
.ria eht ni pu teg ot deganam s'dos evarb emoS
RAOR ni deraeppa evah seirots trohs esohw retirw dna naicisum a
.toob ot naicitcat tnaillirb a dna ,reylf doog ydoolb A"
.sevil ruo htiw no teg ot tseb level ruo gniod
,lardehnA yb
.cinotatac s'eh llit gniknird yb thgin ta speels ylno eh wonk I dna
a – ciler denekcalb dna deraes yreve htiw
.213 si nwo ym otno depmats rebmun ehT
,spmac tliub-esoprup deretne sdnasuoht eht yb sevlowereW .tnemnretni yratnulov fo dnik a ot deerga yeht ,daetsnI
,swodniw-yab thgirb espmilg I mih dniheb
,segalliv srednalF fo bewredips a si yhpargotrac enilesab ehT
,t'ndluohs ylbaborp I wonk I
.'nitsaw-a s'emiT
".ni emoc esaelP
;ffo tfel ekcleoB dna nnamlemmI erehw thgir pu gnikcip ,satsaJ eht gnisinagroer neeB
.moor eht fo ertnec eht ni erauqs-ruof gnidnats elbat suomrone na dna
,yerruS  lliH niggiB
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.pu snips laid retemitla ehT
.seriw-gniggir eht hguorht gnimaercs strats dniw eht sreggirt eht ot tfihs sbmuht ym sa dna
.yawyna ,letni tsetal eht ot gnidroccA
.gnisseug m'I ,'ercassam' rof ese-ymrA hsitirB si 'wohs a fo
.sgnilgdelf sih did nairtsuA yldnik siht naht erom nerdlihc rieht no detod reve stnerap on ,llits
.esarhp elgnis taht ni deirrac esromer eniuneg fo enotrednu na saw ereht raews dluoc I os neve tub
.rood eht hguorht em wodahs ,neddibnu ,sPM owt ehT
.flow a nrob t'nsaw I ,ees uoy esuaceb
;thgin ta ylf ot ton dnet stolip namuH
.rab reddur dnah-tfel eht toob dna
.eciohc ylno rieht hcum ytterp si hcihw
".ecnarF nrehtron ni pu gniwerb wohs a fo tib a toG
.etatiseh ton od emit siht ohw ,sPM owt eht ot ylprahs sdon eH ".sih
.esoper ta dna serawanu thguac ,sucriC gniylF eht :erom dna neetfif ,net ,sretturts-eev eht ,sreswob lortep eht
,seno suoremun eht ,snamuh
.nwod gnilbmut emac yllanif ecifide liarf taht
;elttorht eht pu nepo I sa sraor enigne ehT
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.cra s’relleporp a hguorht erif ot dezinorhcnys snug-
,11 leffatsdgaJ rof stolip namreG eht fo tseb eht dekcipyrrehc s'eh
– etaler dluoc nam ro flow fo seirotsih yna sa gnol sa rof ,yllaer
.tnelis llaf seirasrevda ym fo snug eht
...gnihtyna seirt eh fi mih pleh nevaeH
.selur dercas owt yb devil dah sevlowerew
,thgis ym fo tuo ,erehwemos esuaceb
– sdne thgifgod eht woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.daerps tabmoc cissalc a ni kcab rehtruf dna rehgih elttil a gniylf s'eh dna ,eulb dna neerg sdnomaid fo
,ecalp eht saw mahnraF dna ,raey eht saw 2191  .thgilF  .noissesbo dnof dnuofwen ym ni flesym esremmi ot
.htap rieht otni thgir stfird eof ym fo egalesuf eht dna
.gnihtolc namuh fo hctits a ton gniraew s'ohw
,su fo owt eht neewteb tsuj tnemmoc gnikoj-flah ,suoires-flah A
.ecnaegnev rettib emos tcaxe ot naht erom gnihton ekil d'ohw nem fo egatrohs on saw ereht
?stolip doog hcus rof ekam dluow sevlowerew taht detciderp evah dluoc ohW
.mra sih psalc ot tuo hcaer I eslupmi nO
,fi – ecalp ni tup eb thgim noitcetorp fo tros emos ,esruoc fO
– sraey fo sdnasuoht roF  2 fo
.dniheb ecnalg rehtonA
.meht tsniaga stcaf eseht esu nac I
.thgil lanrefni na htiw dehtab si dleifria detsaved eht fo yteritne eht
:dengised saw ehs hcihw rof ksat elgnis eht htiw no teg ot tneitapmi
.evoba hgih swollaws eht ekil tsuj gnis dna poows dluow oot ew nehw emit eht fo gnimaerd
.tsuahxe hcae morf raeps emalf thgirb fo skaerts
.gnimoc rof uoy knahT .repooC"
,tnatsni eht nopU
.wobniar eht fo ruoloc yreve ni pu detniap ,sretturts-eev III.D sortablA wen esoht tog ev'yehT
.tcepser ym rof hguone s'taht dna ,tolip a s'eh ;eralf slirtson ym leef I
.ma I skniht eh ruc eht ekil tsuj
.susreV sevlowereW ni dna
;smaerd yppah fo ffuts eht ,yromem otni ylwols delttes thgilf fo syad yM
,denosaer yeht ,yleruS
.yawa sdray derdnuh owt tuoba ,em sdrawot thgiarts gnimoc dna nac yeht sa drah sa gnibmilc llits ,era yeht ereht dnA
;rood yvaeh eht dniheb morf seciov pu kcip srae flow yM
*******  .gnis ot evol did syawla ehs ,drib yM
,revo drah kcits eht maj ,esruc a tuo pley I
,erofeb tem reven ev'eW ".gnimoc
.sgniht esoht yas yeht erofeb tohsrae fo tuo m'I erus ekam ll'yeht meht rof doog s'tahw wonk yeht fi tub