.uoy esimorp I ,neppah did yllaer tahT“
,ecnis reve dlrow eht rednaw ot denmednoc neeb dna
,syadiloh samtsirhC eht ni niaga yrt ot deerga eW
.xobhctam ym tuo werd dna
,niatpaC eht fo tnorf ni ssenedur sih rof mih otni yal ot denrut I .taps kcoJ
.liat sti gnidnuorrus erif elap fo llab a
.wolg gnirekcilf sti ni sepahs gnivom ,gnicanem fo lluf dekool htaeneb wolloh ehT
.ylesolc erom dekool I tub ,nek t’ndid I
”?rail a em gnillac uoy erA“ .dehgual eh
.gniticxe erom neve dnuos ti edam hcihw
”.ereh tuo uoy deggard evah ot yrros m’I
,demmad eb ot smaerts
,elim retrauq a morf reficul a fo eralf eht tegrat dluoc srepins ymenE
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY,syawla sA
.enips ym gnola tfil ruf eht tlef I dna
- sredluohs reh dnuora mra ym tup I oS
,ti rof gnikool neeb t’ndah uoy fi ti nees evah t’ndluow uoy tniaf os ,hcnert ruo morF
.emit eht ta hsittocS nodnoL eht fo emos htiw hcnert a gnirahs erew eW
”,erofeb nees ev’I sag on ekil s’ti
’!pots ,ecarG’“ .kniht dna
.egdir txen eht revo tsuj gnirevoh saw ti litnu
.xawseeb fo hcni-flah eht tuo dellup I gnilbbarcs citnarf emos retfA
gnillac ,redluohs ym gnikahs ecarG saw
,nmelos saw eciov siH
resolc on worg ot demees thgil ehT
.ti otni gnoldaeh dehsur evah dluow I ,deppirt t’ndah I fI
,ssapmoc eht fo trofmoc eht etipsed dna
,etunim yrev taht sdoow sih hguorht gnipmor kcab saw eh
.yltnelis gnihctaw erew dna
,htap eht morf yawa srellevart yrawnu derul ehs dias saw ti ,yawynA .erif no
.htmraw dna thgil rof eldnac elttil a ylno htiw
,dlog yriaf toN .dlog saw ti—
”.ti htiw od lla dluoc ew kniht I
.ti dellac evah d’I ,live
ti til dna eldnac eht pu dekcip ecarG
,debmilc eb ot seert erew erehT
”.hcniP ,oot ,siht fo giws a htiw od dluoc uoy fi sa kool uoY“
”!cinyc dlo uoy ,hcniP“
.lleps a rof tuo emoc dah noom eht spahrep dna
,xob eht fo edis eht tsniaga tsaf dna drah eerht rebmun reficul dehctarcs I
”,selgob eht rof s’tI“
elat a fo elat a ,noitaredisnoc ruoy rof thginot os dnA
”.nek ey ,evE ’swollaH llA s’tI
.tac ydal a saw
.ti gniyned tniop on saw erehT ”.riS“
zzum sih no noisserpxe eht morF
”,seirreJ no dekrow ti fi lufesu erom thgis nmad a eb dluow tI“  .niaga dias kcoJ
.ecaf sti ni seloh eht hguorht derekcilf thgileldnac ehT
,sgnikcots ym ni tuo tperc neht
.seert eht gnoma yaw ym esol thgim I dna
.sag hsram gnimalf fo sllab ylekil tsom
”.hgual ot ton uoy knaht lliw I
,eciohc a spahrep
”?od ot dediced I dna ecarG tahw sseug uoy naC“ .dennirg xoff
tser eht lla dna sgnoL-A-boB eht
.boj ysae na dah ti
- drah ti koot xoff niatpaC
.sdnalwol eht morf tibbar gnuoy a derepsihw ”,nretnal-a-geP“
,wollef eno rebmemer I .stlik rieht dna
.snalp dna spam pu gniward tneps saw emit ruo fo tser ehT
.dnaL s’naM oN ot dna
.seye sih ni tseretni ,dias eh
.erac t’ndid I tub ,swoble eht ot dekaos saw I
,wap ym fo kcab eht ekil sdoow esoht wenk I thgilyad nI“
.dum eht ni gniggard reddur sih htiw syawla sa yraew gnikool
,enil thgiarts a ni gniklaw peek ot deirt eW
”.thgil a pu tnes laroproC eht yas retteb
,emas eht lla elat s’xoff gniraeh pleh t’ndluoc I
.tnuh tsohg a no sdoow eht otni erutnev ot nos sih rof neeb dah ti suoregnad woh tuo gnitniop
,sdnim rieht ni hserf yrots taht htiw
,sey—flesreh liaT-tnruB-ynneJ nevE
”,reporp pu dniw eht tog ev’yehT“
,gninnur morf reh pots ot fi sa
.pu su pirt ot sekans ekil dnuorg eht gnola derehtils stoor eht dna
”’!ytneB ,daed eb t’noD
.raw naht srorroh rehto era ereht teY
.nretnal-ykcaj eht morf thgil eht ni gnitnilg
!lwo na ylno saw tI‘ .dellac I
.su no peelsa gnillaf og t’noD
sehtolc ym revo no samajyp ym tup I
.seinul fo riap a ekil gnilggig detrats htob ew mraf eht fo tohsrae fo tuo erew ew sa noos sA
.nrab s’ecarG ni tool ruo dih eW
.sworb kcalb yhsub esoht rednu morf em ta deralg eH
,enas erew meht fo tsoM
.redluohs ym revo kool a dekaens I
sepahs lufwa ees ot nageb I dna
tsohg eht hpargotohp dluoc ew os einworB xob sih reh dnel ot srehtorb reh fo eno dedausrep neve dah ecarG
.mih ediseb petserif eht no nwod skrow elohw eht tes dna
.hguone tuoba tsuj dah d’ew os ro ruoh na rof derednaw dah ew emit eht yb tub
.elat eht llet ot evil dluow eh
.yaw eht no nekcihc dloc fo gel a ot flesym gnipleh
.part a fo swaj eht otni gniklaw erew ew tsrow tA
,hguone tnemhsinup eb ot nosaes reggur fo elddim eht ni thgir elkna dekcorc a denokcer elpoep nwo yM
,lwoy gnittilpsrae na saw erehT“
”...re ,reh tes liveD eht taht lufdaerd os emirc a dettimmoc dah ehs
,noitidepxe eht rof deen d’ew thguoht ew esle gnihtyna dna
.tenoyab sih htiw gnihtemos ta yawa gnikcah
,olleH“  .su no tceffe taht dah eh
.serutaerc elttil denethgirf ,yllis
.wap ym ot no deppird xaw toh emos dna ,krad eht ni deppets-sim I
.ykcul erew ew fi
,emoh og ew tseggus ot tsrif eht eb ot detnaw su fo rehtieN
,sthgil gnitaolf dnasuoht dnasuoht a fo thguoht I
.egnahc a edam taht—
,su no ekoj a gniyalp saw eh sevlesruo dlot
.til ,eldnac eht saw wap rehto reh nI
.yawa selgob eht peek eaT“
”.esac ni tsuj ,uoy fo lla ,no sksaM“
.woleb morf yrc tniaf a saw ereht
,derob dna dloc erew eW
- em troppus ot deganam ehs woh wonk t’nod I
.tuokool a peek ot pets-erif eht no flesym dekrap I os
.yltnatsni desaec elbbab eht dna
.rehtegot ffo dehcrul ew dna
,peelsa llaf ot setunim wef a meht evag I
,gnikatrednu na etiuq neeb evah tsum hcihw
.ni gniward erew sthgin eht nehw
.seil emoh noitcerid hcihw ni erus etiuq ton er’uoy fi esu hcum t’nsi ssapmoc a tub
.htaed ym ot eb dluohs ti fi neve
’,hO‘ .ereht gnihton saw ereht tub
- oot ,wap ym ni esle gnihtemos saw erehT
”,kcoJ ,erom em lleT“
.hctaw no neeb evah dluohs ew nehw detcartsid gnieb enoyreve tuoba ro
”.reetnulov a deen I
,doof fo sparcs ,sdne eldnac detcelloc ew keew llA
.riS ,eralf yna thgil t’ndiD“
,ecneidua sih sdrawot ecaf sti dah eH
pu demool nrab eht tsal ta tub
.eman s’ecarG tuo ekam dluoc ew resolc werd ew nehw dna
.gnihtyna ni detseretni niatpaC eht nees d’I ecnis elihw a saw tI
.taht ekil gniht ylgu na gnikam sruoh dneps dluow enoyna yhw enigami t’ndluoc I
,eenk s’elcnu rieht ta sbuc eerferac fo selkcuhc eht t’nerew selkcuhc riehT
.rorret enilef erup fo keirhs a
.devas erew eW .gnihcraes tuo
.dettops eb dluow rekcilf tniaf eht taht thginot regnad hguone elttil saw ereht tub
’,lwo dlo diputs a ylno saw tI’“ ’!enog
ym( ylssorc dias I
.goD fO tsohG ehT dellac
enohs nretnal-ykcaj eht
.ymra eht ni ecneirepxe taht dah lla dah ew
,mood ruo ot su gnirul no tneb
,detooh lwo na ro deltsur sevael eht revenehw keirhs dna rehto hcae hctulc ot nuf saw ti dna ,tsrif ta ytlevon a saw tI
.daeh s’xoff no ylfeirb wap sih dial retto ehT
.detrotsid dna ywolley saw thgil egnarts eht
.dleifelttab a dnuora gnignah eb thgim stirips teiuqnu ynam woh tsuj denigami lla ew elihw ecnelis saw erehT
,yllaer ,stik erem erew meht fo emoS
,mih htiw gniog saw I dalg saw I dnA
.ffo don ot detrats I revenehw liat ym gnitib yb ekawa flesym tpek dna
,ybboR ekil em esaet ot mih rof detiaw I ”.drow yM !uoY
.sdoow eht sdrawot ffo elots ew sa ytefas rof swap dleh ew gnittimda dnim t’nod I
.mra ym no wap a dial xoff tub
.cifitneics ylbirret eb ot gniog lla saw tI
,erusaert taerg a dedraug ohw yriaf a saw ehs dias ohw esoht erew ereht tuB“
,ti fo dne eht ta lirvoB fo gum a dna htab toh a su evig ot muM on saw ereht tuB
”,ytneB saw em rof eman tep s’ecarG“
,krad eht ni suoregnad erew smaerts dna sgob eht esuaceb saw ti dias elpoep yM“ .deunitnoc xoff
.dnuorg yddum eht no htgnel-lluf
,tsohg a nees d’yeht kniht enoyna ekam ot hguone
.erom yna srehcterts deen t’ndid taht sesac eht fo swap eht gnidloh dnaL s’naM oN ni tuo mih nees d’I dna
,gof taht ni ,thgin taht tuB
ti‘ ,detsisni ecarG ’,oN’“
.niahc fo htgnel a tuo gnihsif saw dna
.mih rof no temleh s’dos yllis eht tup ot dah I
,gnihtyna gniyrt meht enigami t’ndluoc I taht yhtlif os saw rehtaew ehT
,”liaT-tnruB-ynneJ“
,esion eht sdrawot detnirps I
.tros doog a saw erdaP eht tub
.gob peed a fo egde eht no erew ew was I dna
,kcab emoc dah eh fi dnA .yldliw ,ylfeirb
,gnillac seciov raeh dluoc eW
,ylwols devlover ti os
,thguoht I ,tsohg a s’eH
.em rof ti retfa kool ehs detseggus retaM nehw knits a pu dekcik I dna
”?snoino gnimalf esoht fo senil eht gnola gnihtemoS
,nar dna liat denrut eW
,thgilyad ni did ti naht regnol hcum demees kcart ehT“
,denrael ecnis evah I ,era—
taht retfa liaT-tnruB-ynneJ fo sgnithgis erom on erew erehT“
noitatneserp neewollaH laiceps a fo trap sa
”?pahc dlo ,uoy pleh I fi klaw uoy naC“
.noitisoporp tnereffid yrev a saw emitthgin tub
”,riS ,neht ,em dna uoy ekil skooL“
.delkniwt seye sih tub
seirots tsohg dekil yllaer reven ev’I si hturt ehT
.retaw yddum eht otni swap ym gnignulp
”.sbbiT laroproC .riS ,eM“
.thgil etihw fo llab a saw
.deppans I ”?ereht s’ohW“
stnecca kciht rieht fo suovren erew tol ruo elihw
.uoy nethgirf ot gniog saw ti thguoht uoy esuaceb tub
.hsalf tnecserohpsohp eht ni gniwolg
.tekcop sih morf eldnac fo pmuts a dellup dna pal sih morf sgnileep dehsurb tocS ehT ”.su llet mih teL
,elddup a otni eldnac eht deppord dah I flesym pleh dluoc I erofeB
.dluoc ew revenehw seirots eht ot denetsil I dna ecarG tuB
,yllufnrocs ,dias eh
,ria eht ni gnignah etihw gnihtemos was ew ,did ti sA
.dehctip-hgih dna
.yrots rieht rof niatpaC eht dnuora derehtag yeht nehw sa ylneek os ti tlef reven d’I dna
.nageb eh ”,doow hceeb gib a saw ereht
llawnroC morf regdab a ni tup ”!sthgil-yksiP“
.seert eht gnoma tsohg a nees d’yeht raews ot yppah erew sklof fo ytnelP“
?nopaew wen a s’ti ebyaM“
.tsaeb deggel-evif egnarts emos ekil gnola gnilbboh
,yltnelis ,tops eht no bob ot deunitnoc tub
”?ot pu uoy era tahW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.seirots neewollaH gnidaer er’ew keew siht dna
?uoy dnuora lla hguone naht erom s’ereht nehw
”?ti tuoba raeh ot erac uoy dluoW“
.cinap ot gnitrats saw I dna
”!nretnaL ybboH eht ti dellac eW !oot eno dah eW“
.eralf taht til uoy ykcul ylloj saw ti ,yas I
.niagrab eht otni tsol spahrep
.revlover ym no wap eno ,deltsirb I
,yellaV tibbaR morf
.deraeppasid dah liaT-tnruB-ynneJ
.taht ta elttil a desuor sbbiT
tirips live na saw yllaer ti fI .su gnikcom
epor fo htgnel a ekil
- mih dekil lla ew dna ,skcirt fo lluf syawla saw eH
,eldnac fo eceip tsal ruo gnidloh saw I“
.sworbeye dna ehcatsuom lla
.wenk reven uoy tub
vos taht tuo dellup uoy nehw wap ruoy fo tuo gnitae meht dah uoY .riS
liat gnimalf taht ta
su no hguot neeb dah keew tsal ehT
”.elbiB eht fo sgnihcaet eht no ssap ot yaw a sa hcruhC eht yb desu erew seirots tsohg
- ecaf ecin yrev a ton tub
pu tnew llehs rats a nehw gnizeerf
,flesym tuoba saw I naht
.)kcoJ saw yllaer eman s’eno siht tub ,esruoc fo ,kcoJ lla meht dellac ew(
”.yenom tekcop s’htnom a rof nruter ni—
’.erif no saw liat reh dnA
gob eht ni dnuof I nioc tahT
ti ni eloh a derob I
,rebotcO ni yad tsal eht nO
,dil a ekil detca ti os pot pinrut eht decalper eH
,tniop emos ta dne ot dah doow eht taht sdnuorg eht no
,dnegel lavir a nI
,thgileldnac gnirekcilf eht ni srehto eht fo secaf eht gnihctaW
.htuom dna eson ,seye eht rof seloh gnihcnup
…uoy ot tfel si eciohc taht hguoht
,rood yrellucs eht desu I
.samtsirhC saw ti ekil pu til sdal esoht ,uoy llet I
,gnilaeppa ssel tol a demees ylneddus gnitnuh-tsohG
.yad siht ot taht fo tliug eht yrrac I dna ,eveileb I ,reh deppihw rehtaf s’ecarG“
.nwo rieht fo secalp ralimis ni erew sdal eht dna
.lla dna ti od ot meht decnivnoc evah dluoc xoff niatpaC
,ssenkcalb rettu eht nI
,nretnaL-ybboH eht dna
”.tcaf ni ,deifirreT .diarfa er’uoy
.pu deffulf saw ruf reh lla tub ,deksa I nehw
,neht srorroh fo gnag reporp a dekool lla eW
,thgil ot hctam a gnitteg emit a fo ecued eht dah eH
,su ta dekool xoff niatpaC
.daehrevo demaercs llehs a sa netsil ot desuap eH
,evom dluoc ew erofeB
.tseW og sekolb wef a dah d’ew dna
,dna ”!seldnac-esproC“
.taht naht liated erom yna ni ti ees ot hguone raen tog reve ydoboN
.deb eht tew d’I hcum os em eracs ot desu eh dna spup erew I dna ybboR rehtorb ym ecnis ton—
.krad eht ni enola dna tsol
,llab flog a fo ezis eht daeh ym no pmub a saw erehT“
,egalliv eht ni noitatuper live na dah aera ehT“
.dnaL s’naM oN ssorca sleehwtrac nrut dna tniap suonimul ni sevlesmeht revoc
.detanicsaf erew eW
.sdraobkcud eht rednu retaw yddum eht gnilppir
denepeed ssenkrad eht erofeb
,hcniP treblA tnanetueiL“
.seno larutanrepus yna ffo dnim ym tpek
ti ni dnuora gnidaw lla erew ew dna
,seceipeye acim hguorht neeS
.thgir lla fo tib a ekil dekool selbategev toor neve dna hguorht ti edam t’ndah sniart ylppus eht nehw
,daeh s’sbbiT gnildarc saw eh devirra I emit eht yB .dewollof I dna
tekcop ym otni ti deppils I
ehT‘ .gnilbbab saw ecarG
.esle gnihtyna ro
,saw eh pahc elttil suoicoref
!tcerroc yletulosbA“
.ees ot dnuor depeep dna
.dnarre s’loof a no erew ew erus saw I
.snoititsrepus lekoy yna gniveileb ot dettimda evah t’ndluow yehT
thgil etihw gnilzzad htiw dellif erew seye yM
,ylecin kcirt eht od dluow eloh llehs deggolretaw A
,ti yned t’ndid I
csid dlog yvaeh eht delgnad eH
,wap a ni dleh nretnal a fo thgieh eht dias emos
,eert eht tsniaga pu tis ot em depleh ecarG
.deltsur sehcnarb rieht dna
.dellepsid erutcip eht litnu rae eht dniheb ecreif flesym dehctarcs I
,hsiwolley ro ,etihw saw tI
;rethgual fo rumrum wol a saw erehT
.smoordeb rieht ot og retaM dna retaP draeh I tsal tA
,enog dah eh eveileb t’ndluoc eW
.eno rettib a saw raW eht fo nmutua dnoces ehT  reetyksuH yb ”liaT-tnruB-ynneJ“   .goD fo tsohG eht no
,nosaer doog on rof tew dna dloc
”!doolb ruoy llihc lliw tI
.ees sdal eht tel ot enod evah t’ndluow ti tub
”.sgniraeb s’eno esol ot ysae ylbirret os s’ti si
,enips ym no pu dnats ruf eht ekam ot hguone eiree saw tI
.evlav tsuahxe eht dnuora dias I
.gnirad ym fo duorp ylterces saw retaP tcepsus I dna
hguohtla ,eldnac eht gnithgil dna tekcop tekcaj ym ni sehctam eht gnidnif
.sreddal eht pu dennihs ew sa derettum I
,esruoc fo ,seert hguorht gniklaw htiw elbuort ehT“
,tuogud eht ot ecnartne eht ni flesmih delttes niatpaC ehT
derettum enoemos nehT
,raw fo srorroh eht fo dias neeb sah hcuM
!elat yracs a s’ti“
denokcer I ,pinrut A
.efil otni deralf ti dna
,tnemom gnol a rof rehto hcae ta dekool I dna xoff
.redluohs sih no gnuls gab savnac eht ot tnew wap s’niatpaC ehT ”?saG“
,ni tes t’ndid energnag dna
.tohspans a ekat ot thguoht su fo rehtien ylniatreC
pots em edam ssenkcalb neddus ehT
.enog erew seilppus doof ruo dna sdne eldnac fo tuo gninnur erew ew
.tuo tnew dna delzzif ti erehw
.dlihc ym ,yrots rieht nerdlihc eht llet snaem lla yB“
.eruliaf a noitidepxe eht decnuonorp I gnirevihs saw ecarG was I nehw tub
’!kciuq ,ytneB ,kooL’“
.ylneek em ta dekool xoff .egdirtrac 554. a htiw ti ta pop a dah d’I erofeb luos ym ekat tsohg yna tel ot dnetni t’ndid I
s’ehs‘ ,detnioppasid gnidnuos ,dias ehs
,’dednworD‘ .denword dna gob eht ni nwod dekcus eb ot no meht gnidael
rorroh tnevni yhW“
.rehtaew eht gnissucsid fi sa ,ylsselerac dias niatpaC eht
,esnesnon saw ti thguoht uoy esuaceb yrots ym no kcab ruoy nrut t’ndid uoY“
.lortap a morf nruter ot deliaf sbbiT gnuoy nehw ,gninrom taht emoc dah warts lanif ehT
.gel sih hguorht naelc eloh tellub a saw erehT
,reetyksuH yb uoy rof daer dna nettirw
.dluoc I revenehw
wap sih pu dleh xoff niatpaC
,senil gnisoppo eht sdrawot delleviws erew srae ym hguohT
.hguoht ,niatpaC eht ot snoitaluceps eseht fo yna gniciov erofeb taorht nwo ym tuc evah dluow I .enimdnal a ro
.dehctaw dna em ot txen flesmih doots eh
gnihgual erew yeht tsael tA
.sevren fo etats a ni dna deritrevo
”,esruoc fo ,detnuah saw tI“
.devirra eh ecnis drow a nekops ylerab dah ohw
,tfad dednuos evah dluohs tI
.dellac I ”,riS ,no oG“
dehsilbup yllanigiro
,yawynA  .thgil eiree
,tnemeticxe fo rumrum a draeh I ”...tcaf nI
.eenk sih no nretnal-ykcaj eht dna mih dnuora ylisoc delruc liat sih htiw
,emoh og ot detnaw tsuj dna sessol yvaeh dereffus dah yehT
.selcric ni dnuor gniog erew ew diarfa ylbirroh saw I
,reh erofeb ria eht ni gnitaolf deraeppa dah ydal tac siht
owt fo snoitanigami evitcarevo eht yb yawa denialpxe eb t’ndluoc taht deneppah gnihtoN
”,seirots tsohg yna gnillet og dluohs uoy nokcer t’nod I“
yad yranidro na nO
.redluohs ym ot rehto eht deppalc dna
.esruoc fo ,was ecarG tahw ees t’ndid I
,em dnif ot deganam dah ecarG dezama saw I
”.tocsam ykcul fo tros emos gnikam s’dal sihT“
”!riS ,xoff niatpaC ,seY“
hsalf gnirewsna na thguac I
tib tsethgils eht tsuj hctiwt liat sih was I dna
”,nretnal-ykcaj a ’nikam m’I“
.flesym pleh dluoc I erofeb dekrab I ”!kooL“
cinut sih fo nottub pot eht enodnu dah xoff
secaf ’sdal eht no skool eht morF
.lworg ot gnitnaw flesym tlef I dna
”,niatpaC ,siht fo hguone tuoba dah ev’I“
.ti tuoba driew gnihton htiw ,thgil ylhtrae ,tsenoh ,reporp A
sih ni wap ym depsalc eh tub
,doolb hcum oot tsol t’ndah eh dedivorP
.niaga regdab hsinroC eht saw tahT
,klat egalliv eht ot pots a tup xoff droL tcepsus I ,kcab gnikooL
.htuom s’ybbat eht otni ksalf pih sih morf ydnarb gnippit
.hturt eht gnillet saw ehs sraews llits ehS
.nootalp eht ta daeh ym gnikahs ,dias I
.buts a ot nwod denrub dah hcihw
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.ti til dna ,pinrut eht fo esab eht ni ti kcuts
,gnitniop saw ehs erehw dekool I ’!ydal
,deirav snoitpircsed ehT
,revlis ot yerg morf ti dnuora gof eht gninrut
slirep laer yrev eht tuoba flesym ot gnilbmurG
.niaga depmuls daeh siH
.dias eb ot sniamer ,tbuod on ,hcum dna
.eriw debrab fo dnarts a tuc ot yllanoisacco gnisuap dna
,erihsdaP ni ,pu werg I erehW“
,su revo wol mool ot demees sehcnarb kcalb ehT
- reirret needrebA na
.eert a tsniaga daeh ym tih ot ria eht hguorht welf I dna elkna ym debbarg gnihtemos tub
.ekil tlef ti ,nioc a
,swodahs driew tsac evird eht gnola seert ehT
.fo llet draeh I taht enon ,tsael ta—
,flesym ylreporp pu dniw eht dah I
- gaw ot trats liat ym dna nethgiarts kcab ym tlef I
”.hcniP ,rehtien eM“ ”.ti ekil t’nod I“
,elbisnes yats ot dah enoemoS
,ekirts t’ndluow deirt I owt tsrif ehT“
,xoff dnuora sreidlos fo gnir regae eht was eh nehW
”.erehwyna ti tog evah dluoc uoy hguoht neve—
,hcniP ,sksa enoyna fI“
,dias eh ”,uoy nraw I“
,elttil a eldnac eht fo dne eht detlem eh dah eh nehw tub
,derit teg dluow ew tseb tA
gnorw od t’ndid I epoh I .seY“
”.nac llits ew elihw kcab og s’teL“ .dias I
thgin ta noitar mur eht tsuj
erif ymene rednu pot eht revo gniog diarfa ssel neeb ev’I
taht sdrawot gniklaw saw I naht
.slacimehc fo gnat sti htiw ria elats eht ni koot I sa srae ym ni depsar htaerb yM
”.spuW-rellaW eht saw sruO“
,ees ot emoc dah ew gniht yrev eht neeb evah thgim tI“
,regral werg thgil eht tsal tA
,snihs ruo dekrab dna sdaeh ruo depmub dah ew
,gof eht otni gnirats
”.ereh erdaP eht fo tnorf ni esnesnon nehtaeh taht lla tuops t’ndluohs uoy ,yawynA .thgir ton s’tI
.dnaL s’naM oN ni tuo
.toor eert a yldetbuodnu saw elkna ym dnuora tlef I hctulc dloc ehT
.kcatta sag a morf mih tcetorp dluoc ti thguoht eh fi sa tsehc sih ot ti gnihctulc
.seye yssalg ,eguh dna sdaeh sselepahs ruo htiw
,ecnelis ni htrae pu-denruhc eht hguorht deggols ew
nretnal-ykcaj eht tes d’ew ,emoh kcaB“
.pal sih morf gnilbmut nretnal-ykcaj eht ,pu doots eH
?tser eht dna yffaT dna niktaW dna slliW—
.yadirF a saw nesohc dah ew thgin ehT“
.enod evah tsum ehs tahw si taht
,etulosba saw ssenkrad ehT
.rebos neve erew meht fo emos dna
”liaT-tnruB-ynneJ“ saw sihT
.no desserp I tub ,denaorg dna derettum sdal ehT .dias I
.delims dah ti dna
.meht tsurt t’ndid ew dna su tsurt t’ndid yehT
,tuo yrc reh edam dah tahw saw tahT
”?ereh no gniog s’tahW .hcniP
.ngierevos nahtebazilE na tub
,etirw ro daer dluoc wef nehw syad eht nI
tnruB-ynneJ dellac
.hcniP tnanetueiL ,yrartnoc eht nO“
.ksud retfa tsuj kcatta ot dekil ymene ehT
.tuo tsrub setavirp eht fo eno ”!sgnol-a-boB“
”!erusaert eht dniF“
neewollaH lacirotsiH
”,hcniP ,yaw rehto yna ti dah evah t’ndluoW“
.dias eh ”,buc a saw I nehw deneppah taht gnihtemos fo em sdnimer tahT“ .feihcsim htiw
,nwod gnimoc erew seinniM eht elihw rehcterts a fo dne sih tfil mih nees d’I
.drawoc a saw I kniht ot reh tnaw t’ndid I woh dna
.denialpxe reirret elttil eht
.neht tsuj yb emac niatpaC ehT
.elzzum dna swap etihw s’ecarG tuo edam I dna
.hsineerg ebyam ro
,ti otni ecaf a devrac dna
.lotsip yot a dna
,noom eht gnidih ,rekciht nworg dah sduolc ehT
,thgin ydniw a saw tI“
.eno ynnuf a ti ekam d’eh
,sooL dnoceS eht ecnis noigiler rof emit fo tol a dah t’nevah I
,krowtra doog saw tI
,thgil eht yb nward
sruoh rof gniog neeb evah ot demees ew tub
.hguoht ,gniht railucep a uoy lleT“
.)laed taerg a gnitruh erew elkna dna daeh
”.ti tuohtiw uoy dnuof evah reven d’eW
,erofeb seirutnec liveD eht ot luos reh dlos dah ehs taht saw yrots enO .liaT-
.wap hcae ni toob a gnidloh
.etiruovaf a neeb dah sbbiT dna ,ti thguob spahc sih fo yna nehw did syawla eh
.neht ,llew yreV !wohs dooG
,em ot gnidnet saw ecarG elihW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ku.oc.reetyksuh ta
.ydaerla sthgis gnillihc-doolb htiw dellif neeb evah sevil trohs esohw sreidlos fo tub
”,stirips teiuqnu eht dna seitsaeb eht ffo draw eat wodniw eht ni
.tekcarb sag a neeb dah ti fi sa
sretrauqdnih reH“
”.sgniht ffo sdnim rieht ekat dluow elat yllis taht thguoht I—
,em ediseb elkcuhc erdaP eht draeh I
,ti dellac syawla rehtaf s’ecarG
.seye ym ni elzzad gniregnil eht lepsid ot deknilb I dna
,sbbiT gniwonk dnA
.’yeltneB‘ fo eman nevig ym ecnuonorp t’ndluoc ehs llams erew ew nehw esuaceb“ ,dias eh
…erahs ot dah ew esuaceb ,mih no saw ekoj ehT
,mret-flah samleahciM eht rof ti dennalp eW
,su neewteb mih detfil ew dna no gnisserd dleif a tup I
,egdir eht nwod gnilbmarcs saw niatpaC eht nehT
”.em desuor seciov ruoy llit dloc tuo saw I
dias I ”,kcoJ ,olluH“
,tops eht ot reh kcart ot deganam uoy fi dna
.detulas I ”.xoff niatpaC“
.eson sih debbur eH
.ecnatsid eht ni tuoba gnibbob
.eldnac deffuns a ekil tuo tnew thgil eht tnemom taht tA
,yrots doog a saw tI“
srehto eht lla tuoba tahw
.yllufetarg ksalf eht koot dna
ytefas reh tuoba deirrow erom saw I kniht ot ekil I ’!kcab emoC !ecarG
.oot ti gnikniht erew yeht wenk I
.eurt t’nsaw ti wenk lla ew tub
,dekan pirts ot meht deksa evah llew sa thgim eh
.stiw ruo fo tuo su deifirret ti tub
.kcen ym dnuora ti raew dluoc I os
.tuo lla su gnipiw dna hcnert eht otni gnimoc ti fo ksir eht gninnur ton m’I ,si ti revetahW“ .deddon xoff
si yrots s’yadoT
tnruB-ynneJ saw ehs“ ,ylmrif dias eh
,pinrut eht tuo dewolloh dah eH
.ecnalg suoixna na mih tohs dah xoff wenk dna
thgil a saw ertceps yltsahg eht deerga enoyreve tub
.seert eht evoba detaolf ti taht srehto
.swap deifirret ym morf gnippord sehctam dna eldnac
,won ,decrof erew selggig dna spley ruO
,dnuora yllacitnarf deporg dna seenk ym ot llef I
.srae dna slwoj ym ni ssentoh eht dih thgin eht lufetarg saw I
flesym pleh t’ndluoc I tub ,meht rof ti liops ot gniog saw I taht dab tlef I
.t’ndluow ehs tub ,pleh gnirb dna em evael ot ecarG dlot I
”,egalliv ym ni ,lleW“
,dnuorg eht evoba teef fo elpuoc a yliree gnirevoH
”.kcits a htiw dekop eb ot stib yggob dna
?thgin taht liaT-tnruB-ynneJ dedaerd dna suomaf eht retnuocne yllaer ew diD“
.thgil suoiretsym eht fo ecruos eht dehcaer neve ew erofeb su teg dluow srepins eht rO
,mraf eht ta em rof gnitiaw ecarG fo thguoht I tub
,srehtorb dna stnerap reh saw tI
,neht tsuj devirra erdaP ehT
eye ym fo renroc eht morF
.ytirohtua mih evag sworb yggahs sih rednu gnimaelg seye thgirb eht dna
,ssenisub eht tuoba elbatrofmoc leef t’ndid I—
.stac no neek taht neeb reven ev’I dna ,em neve
”!reppin a saw I nehw me‘ dellac ew tahw s’tahT“
.gel thgir ym no thgiew yna tup t’ndluoc I dna
”.sdrawretfa elat eht llet ot no tnew dna ot esolc ti was ydobon ,tsael tA
,rehtag ot detrats dah sdal rehto ehT
psar hsittocS wol sih tuoba gnihtemos tub
,nerdlihc erew ew dna krad saw ti tuB
wap sti pu dleh dah gniht eht tub
.elgob a neve ro ,spahrep ,eitsaeb A
,ybraen mraf eht morf nettik a ,ecarG dneirf ym htiw ereht deyalp I“
”.emoh rof ffo tes ew dna
.thginot ,ti teg ot nrut s’dos roop rehto emoS
.srekat on erew ereht
.oot gnisir saw dniw eht dna
rebmemer I gniht txen ehT“
!pu ekaw ,ytneB !ytneB‘
.deilper niatpaC eht
,tsartnoc a spahrep ,nosirapmoc A .liaT-
.ot ton drah deirt I hguoht
”,hcniP ,uoy evah ot ykcul m’I“
.ecnatsid eht ni thgil a was I dna ,sdoow eht fo tuo erew ew setunim fo elpuoc a nihtiW
.selddup ni spup ekil
,kcen ym fo kcab eht no htaerb rieht tlef I nrows evah dluoc I
.tneserp eht ot kcab deppans eH
”,hcniP ,oga sraey esoht lla sdoow eht fo tuo em depleh ecarG nehw ekil tsuJ“
,tnatsid os ro elim a flah saw ,emac ti nehw ,pmurc ehT
.dum eht ni ereht tuo deirub luos yreve rof eno
.noom tnecserc eht ssorca gniliob sduolc htiw
.ti hcuot ot tuo dehcaer evah dluoc ew dna secap wef rehtonA
,flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer reetyksuH yb
rebmemer t’ndluoc ehs cinap reh nI
:2 taerT ro kcirT ni
”,tesnus retfa ereht dewolla t’nsaw I dna
.daeh gnipoord s’ybbat eht revo dias xoff
,erom dna tbed yenom tekcop s’ecarG ffo yap ot hguone htroW
dlos ti evah ot flesym gnirb t’ndluoc I tub
.tekcit eht s’taht ,nepo seye esoht peeK
,riS ,sag s’taht fI“
yal I erehw ot reh del ydal eht nehT
?sbbiT ,gniganam uoy era woH
,seno xof naht krad eht ni reneek era seye ’stac tub
.krad yggof eht ni gnilworp
.taht nwonk evah dluohs loof yna fi sa
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ti thguac dna evid a edam kcoJ
,dum ot sehcnert eht ni htrae eht denrut dah niar gnizeerF
”.riS ,uoy knahT“ .dias eh
,petserif eht no gnittis mih ssorca emac I
,ecarG ot gnidroccA“
”.smaerd tsedliw ruoy dnoyeb htlaew dnif dluoc uoy
?hcniP ,uoy era ,lla retfa ,gninetsil era uoy os ,hO“
.kcab su ediug ot
,ssapmoc s’retaP ’deworrob‘ dah I“
.hcniP ,thgir er’uoY“
,semitemos sremraf eht morf meht elots ro deggeb ,thguob ew -
.duorhs a ekil em dnuora depparw dna
,repuosaep ythgilB yna sa kciht sehcnert eht ssorca gniwolb gof a htiw
,level dnuorg ta saw ti dias emoS
,liaT-tnruB-ynneJ fo riah ron edih nees t’ndah ew yllarutaN
,dloc ro ,diarfa gnieb deined ehS
!hcniP ,hsuhS“ .ni tup I