,ytinutroppo eht was miS
taep htiw revo dna revo denrut
,si alusrU ruo nruticat woh wonk ydaerla ew
nav retaeb yttihs rieht ni taes eht rednu saw nug eht esuac‘ depmuj eH
noom eht ot dna seert gnilkrad eht ot dna dnuorg eht no thgil fo elcric mid taht ot syas eh
.thgin eht fo cirbaf eht tsniaga srats sa krats gnidnats ,ssenthgirb
gib a htiw kcab emoc ll’ehS !tiaw uoy tsuJ
,dias miS ,sdaeh kconk ot deen ehs fi dna ,rood eht kcolb ot dedeen ehs fi tsap gnitteg gnihton
,won sraey dna sraey gnidnem neeb d’ehs seno eht
.reliart ro tnet a neve ton
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.hgual hgih a neht ,esuap A
.sllip emos barG ?sllip deen uoY
”.esoht hguorht wom ll’I .revetahw ro srekcinS fo xob elohw a ekil em barg ,haey ,tihs ,hO
nus eht fo egaruoc eht htiw oS
.erots ecneinevnoc taht saw ereht nehw depmuj miS oS
reh lla dna nwarb reh dna smaerd reh dna raeb eht thguac reven
,srats emoceb smra esoht dna
,ti ni erom ytfif tog ebyam
,noom eht tub eno on ot ystruc leetneg a
.skoob fo sroyevrup enif ynam morf dna
.elbmum A  ”!haH ?smodnoC
.noos efil thgiarts eht evil ot teg ll’uoy
,esle enoyna erih ot paehc oot saw renwo eht dna ysub oot saw eh esuaceb
”,eb attog tsuj ,dnal s’enoemos eb attog s’siht
reh evoba slruc dna sehcnuh eh sa sthguoht reh wonk reven ll’ew dna
.wets a fo lleh a ekam
,sredluohs reh fo niatnuom eht dnuora smra ynniks sih teg nac eh os nac eh sa gnol pu dehcterts ,alusrU
,gnikam retfa netsil ot emit eht t’nsah miS esuaceb
,won yb yawa selim ,tuo raf tuB
.flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
,eilrig ,efil ym no raews I
,miS taht wonk ew gninrom eht fo sruoh llams eew eht ni suht dnA
.retsaf staeb traeh s’alusrU ruo taht si ,swonk miS roop lla esruoc fo dna wonk ew lla ,wonk ew llA
.gninnur no speek alusrU ruo dna ,wons dna enots hguorht
.ekat ot mih rof spets elbissop rehto on tsuj saw ereht
,pu hsinif ot emit hguone tog s’eh serugif dna meht sraeh eh ,krelc dna
lla gnikool kcab ’nimoc eb ll’ehS .tiaw uoy tsuJ“
ro srats eht fo thgil
,flesmih sesimorp eh
.pmuj ot tliub tsuj er’yeht ,sklof emoS
,ekil skool taht tahw erutcip tsuj s’teL
gniniart ni dlot yllacisab saw eh taht gnihtyreve morf yawa hguone raf s’eh tub
daor eht nwod saciremAsnarT gib eht fo eno ta revo llup og lla yeht dna tuo nur skcolc ’srekcurt eht neht tuB
.thgin yrev taht deppans ehs saw yas nac ew llA
rehto’t neht eno tsrif
,reh ekil raeb dlo gib ,elcsum eht saw ehs dnA
steeb nworg-hserf yleruS
.tub pleh t’nac ,spmuj miS
,gnipmuj no tpek dna ,sesimorp edam ,rae reh tib dah
taht ni sessertiaw evitcartta ylbanosaer eht dna slaem toh eht dna srewohs toh eht tog ev’yeht erehw
.nalp ym dnatsrednu n’yrt attog uoY .netsil ,yeh
!hsoG .tuo no emoC“ .sllac eh
,pots ton lliw ehs esuaceb seert eht hguorht swolp ehS
esuac gnissuc dna gnipmotS
,ekih erutan a rof og ot gnideen reh ekil lrig gib a enigamI“ .hgih pu
.noom emas yrev taht ebyaM
,em ot sneppaH ?tegrof revE
dna tae nac ew os nac ew tseb peek ruo nrae attoG ?wonk uoy
?wonk uoy ,won thgiarts og
— terref taht ,recnad a hcus syawla
enihs yllacitcarp seert eht dna
.woleb htrae naelc doog eht rof dna noom eht rof dna
thgildaeh dna evots pmac yb gninrad
robal ni reh evoba slruc dna sehcnuh enoemos reve fi dna
,nur ot dnarre kciuq a tsuj tog yeht ebyam
,dias miS tahw s’tahT
.ecid ro sdrac erom on esimorp I dna
,tuo-teg lla sa thgirb gninihs ,rats tsal eno
yllaiceps‘ ,leehw eht dniheb hsittiks lla teg uoy wonk I ,daor eht no tuo uoy kaerf ot tnaw t’ndid I !siht ta kooL
.nav eht pu peek dna sag
,thgiarts og d’yeht reh desimorp miS taht ekat ykcul taht erofeb semit ynam woh tsuj wonk nac ew naht erom yna
.alusrU saw ereht ,depmuj miS erehw dnA
,niaga snrut ,ecno snruT
.yas d’eh ,sniarb eht saw miS
teef reh htaeneb nepo snway htrae eht dna tuo snur niatnuom eht litnu snur ehS
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.sekil ehs erus m’I swohs esoht lla ni ees uoy ahdduB nedlog emos
?ew lliw ,wonk reven ll’ew tub
ro dlihc htiw saw ehs
.niaga pu kcab em hctap ot evah d’uoy dna tsrub annog s’traeh elohw ym ekil leef I hcum os uoy evol I
taorht eht dna eson eht ni thgirb dna naelc steg ria eht erehw pu ,seikcoR eht fo diarfa saw eh
esuaceb etihw tsethgirb fo srats emoceb yeht
fo daol a teg uoy diD !haH ?siht ees uoy oD“
?esoppus uoy ,tsixe yllaer reve ehs did ,reh thguac reven yeht fi dna
?seiballul meht gnis ehs dluoW ?kniht uoy ,meht ssik ehs dluoW .htrae eht morf hserf dekculp
,sboj eht dna steg eh ytinutroppo yreve pmuj attog s’terref eht wonk lla ew
.ymmud gib ay ,eniF“
,sruoy fo teef ’nikcuf gib esoht ot–“
.emit eht lla sgniht elttil tegrof
,sdaeh kconk ro selim nur ro skcor luah ot derac evah thgim ehs naht erom modeerf dna noom eht dna steeb dna
,nwo ruo no yllatot ton er’ew sa gnol os gnihtemos nrae llits attog eW .em wonk uoy
ekil kcor a no gnitatidem ereht pu s’ehs ebyam
,sredluob fo lluf norpa na ekil yawa llaf ylleb reh stel suht dnA
,nwot llams rehtona pu tiH
,boj a retfa
?wonk miS did tuB .stac dna sexof
,ereht teg ew ecno erom owt ro eno tsuj pu tih ew ebyam tub
,enigne na fo ver eht sraeh eh litnu teliot eht no nwod ssa ynniks sih gnittis speek eh os
,enigami ew ,enituor reh ta peek tsuj dluoc thgim alusrU
traeH eht fo ssendliW A
.erac t’nod I
.ssenisub yksir eht fo tuo teg ,sessa ruo krap ,gnihtemos ro mosweN
,daor eht no seye reh speek ehs ,alusrU
,erus eb ot tsuj ,yaw eht no ti od ew ebyam ro
.eb reve ll’I n’regnorts ’nieb morf noitacav a ekat ot gnideen enigamI .yrrebraeb — !hah — ro seldeen enip ni meht yrub
,niaga gninnips ffo si miS dnA  ”!flesruoy rof lla ti evah ll’uoY
sliated etalp eht teg ot saremac eht tsurt dna gnihtyreve ekat srebbor tel ot kcab owt ro keew a
,yad-ot-yad s’taht gnihtemos od og dna efil boj-ot-boj eht fo tuo teg
fo tnorf eht gnola lla spolf yllanif eH ”.won ,edam ti tog eW“
,flesreh meht eldarc dluoc ehs litnu steeb esoht ybab d’ehs taht esoppus nac eW
,oot ,sredluob esohT .eb dluoc sa taf
?siht si tcefrep 'nikcuf woH“
,htrae naelc doog ni teef reh gniyrub fo demaerd ehs netfo woh
,ymmud gib uoy ,fao gib uoy ,uoy evol I dna
thgin eht rof evol reh wohs ot
.llew sa did srehto ylniatreC
,yrd ot tuo gnuh emirp sti tsap
— nwod tsiaw eht morf ylno mih gnihctac sthgil gnikrap esoht ,nav eht fo tnorf eht dnuora gnilriwt dna gnicnad ydaerla s’eH
ll’I dna ,sreh fo ecaf knalb gib taht no nirg bmud
tcerid elbaliava won si hcihw
hguoht ,spahrep ,diarfA
dekcuf eh sa ti ta nuf gnikop morf miS peek ot tuat dleh regnol on evruc tfos-reve taht
.kcab trilf reven tub krims ohw ,yaw esnesnon-on ,yemoh
,shtnom wef a su yub lliw revetahw ro yak‘ xiS
esuac‘ ,rettahc eht dna pissog eht dna srepap eht ni erofeb siht fo tib riaf a draeh lla eW
.epyt eht wonk uoY .oot ,detalosI
!gnilrad uoy evol I ,hsoG
— steeb fo snac gniyub dna sevol ehs wonk lla ew storrac esoht no gnihcnurc llitS
.tliub s’eh woh tsuj ,depmuj miS
,allef roop ,miS dlo thguac yeht
.yawhgih eht fo sedis eht no dekrap srepoort eht tsap ,srac eht tsap ,sdleif eht tsap spoort
skoob dna gnitirw reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.ekat taht ni srallod dnasuoht xis ekil s’erehT
,eye reh fo elkniwt a dniheb gnivael ,ssik a
.kni.oykam ta
htrae naelc doog ni teef reh yrub ot steg ehs tsal ta taht epoh si od nac ew lla dna
.on ,gnicnad toN
— reh ot tuo sllac eh sa no gniog gnihtemos ro elims a tog s’alusrU ylerus dna ,krad eht otni gninnips
,yeH .raed ym ,gnilrad ym ,netsil tuB“
,eb dluoc sa ysae sa nwod pord sredluohs reh gnittel
,htrae naelc doog ni selkna reh ot pu gnidnats
,ekil ew fi ,enigami tsuj nac eW .noom
,luah a fo pord eht ta
— ”kcab tuo steeb fo ssem ’nikcuf elohw a ebyam dna
.yas ylthgir t’nac ew ,gniwonknu yrev sih yb eb ot ti denigami eh tahw
,sworbeye yna gnisiar tuohtiw ekil-yls laer
morf kaerb a ekat ot gnideen enigamI
.reh rof thguob I eno eht sa ysae os efil a gnivah
,nevele ot neves ekil gnihtemos morf ysub era skrelc eht dna ereht hguorht emoc srekcurt fo not a ylbaborp dna daor eht fo edis eht yb tauqs stis taht sgnidliub esoht fo enO
.sgnineve eht ni tuo ruf reh gnihsurb dna
.srae ruoy ni senoc-enip ,taht ekil loof a kool uoY‘ ,yas ll’I dnA
.liat ot pit morf evol fo lluf tsuJ
.llac neht ylno dna
,gninraey reh tub alusrU ruo fo tfel gnihton s’ereht won dnA
,eilrig ,kcans a barG“  .elbmum A
,alusrU ruo thguac reven yeht esuaceB  .wonk ylurt
,ereht pu tup yeht revetahw ro ssalgixelp taht dniheb ,retnuoc taht dniheb gnittis tsuj si krelc eht dna teiuq s’gnihtyreve erehw sruoh wef eseht s’ereht
,yb emoc srekcurt thgin eht erofeb
,wob a fo hsiruolf a ni yawa daerps smra reh stel ehs dnA
)daer dna nettirw( ”pmuJ“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
reh dekcuf eh taht dna reh tlef eh taht dna reh was eh yas ylerus nac eW
?storrac hcnurc ro sdaeh kconk ro selim nur ro skcor luah reve ehs diD
tfos oot gnitteg morf sredluohs esoht peek ot tsuj ereht dna ereh dnuor skcor dlo gib gniluah dna gninrom eht ni snur reh gniod llits
,erus ,lortap etats ro spoc eht llac dluoc eh dna
.raews I ,ymmud giB
.llac eh seod neht ylno dna ,krad eht otni edaf ti sraeh eh neht dna
,tfihs sih retfa efas eht tih ot emit evah neve t’ndid ylbaborp ereht ni allef roop ,tihS“ .timil eht revo evif n’erom on ,daor eht nwod seldnurt navinim gnimussanu eht sa terref taht syas ”?ekat taht
dna tuo nur skcolc ’srekcurt yad eht retfa
.gnidliub eht fo kcab eht dnuora tuo moorhtab eht ot ffo nar eh dna ,revetahw ro ytriht nevele ta teiuq fo tnemom a laets ot dah eh os
,htootwaS morf sllih eht pu pmac taht
tol thgirb esoht rednu serit fo gnilaeuqs htuocnu on ,teiuq
,yllaer ew ylno tser eht tub
.evol fo esimorp erem a naht erom fo tuo eb lliw ti taht epoh si od nac ew lla
,os tsuj reh tif taht sllarevoc esoht ni desserd alusrU
,eh taht reh dlot dah semit ynam woh
ysub oot s’eh ,reh ot evol
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”pmuJ“ saw sihT
,flesmih desimorp eh
.tsrif od attog ew ti ot hcum os s’erehT
?syad erom wef a em rof pu selcsum esoht ’nipeek yako uoy
,pmuj ot tliub nialp tsuj era sklof emos
dna uoy wonk uoy tub
.htooms laer tuo dna ni er’yeht tub
modeerf dna snoom dna steeb dna snedrag
”–tnuc ’nikcuf toh taht ot etib ot evol I wonk uoy srae esoht morf ydob ruoy nwod dna pu raews I
.flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
.enihs ot nrob erew emos tub
.pmuj ot saw ti sa ysae sa gnixaler sredluohS
,ylleb reh gnikcams ,meht htaeneb tuoba lriwt nac eh taht os pu smra reh gnitfil
.revetahw ro sllip ro skcans ruo barg uoy ,reward eht teg ll’I
”'.'niyub m’I efil eht ni ton dna teiuq ni pu dnuob si ecaep ruoy lla ’nikniht loof latot a kool uoY
,miS ekil ,nac eW  .reh devol
?eilrig ,niaga seldeen ni dnuora ’nillor neeb uoY‘ ,yas dna pu pmuj
modeerf fo sraey reh desimorp d’eh shtnom ynam woh
,tuoba gnipmuj dna gniliaw dna gnilley saw eh dna mih thguaC
,smra reh sa thgirb sa nrub yehT
.wonk reven ylekil ll’ew si ’uoy‘ siht ohw hguohT ”–tiaw uoy tsuJ“
,eroc reh ot teiuq
,tah a fo pord eht ta yas syawla dluow ,gniyas tpek
,won sraey rof thgiarts og ot gnitnaw neeb uoy wonk I“
,steeb dna storrac reh wos dna
!alusrU ,alusrU“  .yawa gnihgual
— ?gnihtemos ro ytnewt ekil
,deb ni thgin ta etal reh esimorp d’eH
”.su rof tuo dial llA
.deen uoy gnihtyna ,skcans eht lla barg ,lleH
fo maerd eht demaerd d’ehs semit ynam woh wonk t’nac eW
ro ecneserp reh denifed dna reh dnuora decnad ylno eh ton ro rehtehw tub
,enoemos ot gniklat eb tsum eh taht dna
.gnihtyna sa thgirb sa gninrub ,yks eht ni srats emoceb yeht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
enivid dna gniwonknu yrev taht dnuora ecnad ylno
esuac‘ ,srats
,srettiks dna spmots eh yaw eht yb delbuort si miS roop ruo sseug nac eW
,rehtet sti ta thgit gnikrej etik a ro noom eht ro
.ria thgindim eht otni tsud pu gnikcik
”?yawyna eh saw erehw dna
.seldeen fo teprac eht hguorht ekaw a sevael ehs
.hguorht emit tsrif eht no ti tog ehs ton ro rehtehw semit eerht alusrU yb nalp eht nur d’eH
.elim a nar d’ehs ylerus ,dekconk ehs daeh ro deluah alusrU kcor yreve rof
,noitcelloc yrots tsetal reh ni sraeppa yrots sihT
,erus m’I ,sllih eseht pu ’nissapserT .ymmud giB“
.peels otni thgir gnillor
.uoy evol I hsog tub
,yoj ni ro niap ni ro tsul ni ro
ekil gnidneterp dna reh evoba gnilruc dna gnihcnuh ,reh
liart trid eht pu yaw sti secnuob dna sbob taht thgil kaew nmad a s’ti os ,degrahc thgilhsalf eht ni seirettab eht tpek reven ,gnipmuj ysub oot
.dnoyeb noom eht dna sthgil
?eb ot epoh reve rats a dluoc roloc retteb tahw
.repap saw ti ekil gnihtyna hguorht tuc nac taht ronet ydeer taht htiw gniyas miS enigami nac ew ”,alusrU ,tihS“
?nedrag nwo reh ni
.serohs yddum sti gniklaw yb ecnesba na gninifeD
.krelc eht ees t’ndluoc eh dna no erew sthgil eht dna tol gnikrap ytpme yletelpmoc a dah erots ecneinevnoc eht dna
hcamots s’pos roop emos ni fo daetsni htrae naelc doog emos ni sruoy fo teef esoht yrub ll’uoy retal ro renoos dna
.noom eht dnuora parw ot sratS
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
nihtiw dleh ecaf eht evig dna ,emit tsal eno taht noom eht ot pu hcaer
.ssenesab taht gnidnepsus ,yad fo thgil nialp ni dna
,mih dniheb gnippolf-pilf sih fo liat ssa-ydeggar taht htiw enip burcs dna hsurbegas neewteb gnola gnitteuorip mih enigami ylerus nac uoy tub
,thgin taht reilrae nav eht fo sthgil eht ni gnicnad miS sa ysae sa
d’ohw ,nu’gib eht dna miS
,sedaced desimorp d’eh sraey ynam woh ro
esoht evol uoy wonk I esuac tnorf ni storrac fo wor A !snedrag owT“
,tahw — won sraey ynam os daor eht no neeb eW
,rehto’t dna miS .wodahs a sa tsael ta ,reh nees a’tsum srehtO
psirc taht otni nrub dna yawa llaf yehT
.ekaw rieht ni sdees gnippord
,rehto’t neht dna wap eno tsrif gnikat
,secalp esoht fo eno ,eeS
,dlrow eht fo thgiew eht fo eltnam eht sdehs ehs dnA
.gnipmuj ysub oot s’eh
.ereht deneppah ylraelc dah gnihtemos
eht no neve sgniht worg dluoc ti ekil llems ot seganam wohemos taht rezilitref tihs peehs taht dna
,erots ecneinevnoc siht ,ees tuB
nac eW“ .htaerb sih no rab ydnac eht llems nac ehs ,erus dna
dna ecnad dna leehw srats eht dna
esuac‘ ,ytinutroppo yna ta pmuj ot kciuq saw eh ,wonk uoy ,miS
.sllihtoof eht ni tuo kcab
.peels ot enog d’yeht retfa gnol thgin ta etal depmac erew yeht erehw morf yawa eceip riaf a gnirednaw neeb d’raeb eht dias ereht enoemoS
teef reh ta snioc werht dna dekeirhs revetahw ro tac ro xof
,esruoc‘ ,ereh tuo gnihtoN
?wonk uoy ,og attog tsuj uoy semitemoS
.nedrag nwo yrev ruoy eb lliw htrae taht dna
.dnatsrednu uoy ,rehtegot kconk ot sdaeh erom wef a tsuj ,snur erom wef a tsuJ .erom wef a tsuJ
dna htootwaS hguorht no
,etal oot tsuj s’ti tniop siht ta tub
.rorret ni deliocer dna
,eb ot erehwon ,og ot erehwoN
!srekcinS fo xob a dna srallod dnasuoht xiS
.edam eb ot snalp ro dah eb ot sluah on ylniatrec s’ereht dna
nedrag reh devarc
tuo nar skcolc 'srekcurt esoht lla litnu rof ti gnidloh neeb d’krelC
esuac‘ ,won gnicnad sseldne sih morf gnibbob ton s’ti dna
,reh thguac reveN
,peelsa thgir llef dna reh dekcuf miS retfa thgin taht ,ev’tsum ehs taht retnec neddih a dnuora gnignop-gnip yb
.ot tliub tsuj s’eh ,taht ot pmuj syawla ll’miS
,os tsuj tif taht sllarevoc esoht ekil
,liat sih htiw shgiht reh gnittih
.pudloh ro tsieh a retfa nav eht ni deppoh yeht emit yreve
tsal gnol ta dnA
.selims delimsnu reh lla dna sdrow nekopsnu
,woleb elkniwt nwot eht fo sthgil eht dna sessuc sih sessuc miS
,ti no selim dnasuoht derdnuh elpuoc a htiw gnihtemos fo elttar dna murht eht
,gninepo na sees miS nehw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,eercs dna elahs hguorht ekaw a ekam ot sah ehs dna tuo nur seert eht litnu snur ehS
”pmuJ“   yojne esaelP
esoht dna wodahs gninraey a tub tfel gnihtoN
'?noom eht ta ’nilwoh dna seert ’nibmilc uoY ?reed eht htiw pmor a gnivah ereht tuo neeb uoY
.dne eht ni mih thguac
”.tsrif reward eht barg esruoc fo ,tsirhC“
eht fo lluf dna lufecaep
eht sa rac s’pos roop emos fo dooh eht revo ro noitats sag a ssorca reh ot tuo llac neve d’eh ebyam dna
,hguone gnol reh no seye sih elttes t’now miS
.pots ot epoh ton dluoc ,pots tonnac
.gnikool srehtob eno on erehw tuo srieht fo nav dlo gib taht krap ot ecalp a tsuJ
,netsil d’ohw enoyna dna spoc eht ot gnilbmar
.sniatnuom eht otni pu gnidaeh alusrU nees d’yeht mih dlot nwot ni nwod enoemos
,seikcoR eht ni pu er’yeht neht
,ypmuj mih ekam yeht
.oot ,tegrof uoy semitemoS
ekil tuo poh yehT
?stsieh esoht lla gnola edir dna evil dna tsixE
.taes regnessap eht morf gnipmuj ydaerla s’eh ,miS dnA
.sdaeh emos kconk ot evah tsuj dluow ehs
esuac‘ ,ton ebyam ro dnuos a sekam ehs ebyam dna
.ti deganam yeht esoppus tsuj s’tel dnA
.thgin eht fo kcalb naelc
.nevelE-7 a eb yllautca ot hguone gib ton s’ti tub
gnol tnemrag a ekil esool tfird sgel reh stel ehs dnA
,hguone gnol tsuj deliob steeb fo niks eht sa ysae sa serac ffo gnihguols
ro smaerts ni meht kaos ot sreh fo teef ssa-gib esoht gnikat
,reh erew taht srats eht htiw noom eht ot pu hcaer ot elba si ehs
.storrac reh hcnurc ot neve derac ehs naht erom
.os yas reven dluow eh sa hcus eno erus eb nac ew
,reh dnuora secnad miS dna llirg eht fo tnorf eht tsniaga ediskcab reh gnikrap dna won nav eht tuo si raeb eht dnA  ”!haH ?sllip ruoy teG ?skcanS ?barg uoy esle tahW
.wonk ylurt ,yllaer eW
,terref eht ekil tsuj
.esruoc‘ ,noitisoppus llA
.swodahs gnitfihs gnitsac enip burcs dna hsurb egas htiw
doog eht dna srats si ni sevaw ekam ot sah ehs lla dna
wodahs elbaitasni
.tsedrah reh snur alusrU
.skrow miS woh s’tahT
,thgin taht pmac rieht edam d’yeht erehw morf
esuac ,boj yreve retfa sserttam emas yrev taht otno nwod reh hsup miS
.tresed hgih eht dna dnas eht dna burcs eht hguorht gnola gnikop
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
dna snoitats sag dna serots pu tih
.reward eht tuo esolc ot togrof dna rood tnorf eht kcol ot togrof eh emit siht ylno ,gnirebmemer ta doog saw eh ,krelc rooP
?yeht t’ndah ,peek rieht nrae ot tog dah yeht ,llits tuB
?sserttam taht otno kcab reh hsup miS tel yllaer reve ehs diD
,swalc fo slufdnah esoht htiw flesreh sworruf wolp d’alusrU taht
”,ymmud gib uoy no emoc ,eilrig no emoC
dna saw ehs tneserp yrev woh tsuj wonk yllaer miS diD
esuac‘ ,niorg reh ta barg a htiw detautcnup siht
rehgih reve sesir noom eht sa dnuorg eht nopu tsac
.reh fo retteb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
.od ew esruoc‘ ,did ehs wonk eW
gnittel llitS .sserttam rieht fo dne eht tsap tsuj ,nav eht fo etagliat eht no wets a pu kooc nac ehs os kcuhc paehc htiw og ot — smaerd reh ni esoht fo snoitatimi elap
,evol ym ,raed ym ,alusrU“
,gniyrc strats ebyam dna sessuc dna sessuc dna sessuc eh dna selkna sih dnuora nwod sreward sih ,si eh ereh dna eerf deknay gnieb reward sih sraeh krelc roop dnA
ro emoH niatnuoM
,ekil ecin lla erots eht fo tnorf eht ot pu thgir deppils dna yawhgih eht nwod gniraet emac raeb a dna terref a nehw emit eht eb ot deneppah tsuj siht dnA