",sgniht esoht fo yna nwo I kniht t'nod I"
.yrots tsohg lanoitidart eht fo tnemele tnatropmi nA
,hguoht shtnom eerht doog a yb redlo saw nonreV
.tpmeknu saw egdirB mossolB ot htap ehT
.won erew yeht neht oga dnoces a reduol hcum erew stcesni eht taht erows eh tub
slerriuqs dna ,setoyoc ,sexof ,shateehc ,seiksuh
,tib tsal taht dezisahpme eh
.sbuc gnivahebsim
.pu hcaer ot egaruoc eht dnuof yllanif eh litnu
.sehtolc rieht did os dna
.gnos reh raeh uoy nehw reh s’ti wonk ll'uoY
.thgindim retfa drayhcruhc eht ni toof tes ton oD
.htworg dehctertstuo ni depparw doots ti ,daeha yltceriD
.worros fo esnes gnimlehwrevo na was dna
",kcab og dluohs ew ebyaM"
,enola gnieb fo tcepsorp eht yb denethgirF
.toof sih htaenrednu hcnarb nellaf a gnihcnurc ylduol ,pets sih otni denael nivlA
.teiuq dna ecaep emos htiw tnetnoc yltcefrep saw eh tub
.edahs meht evig ot tuo emoc yeht
.niaga htap eht no detrats yeht erofeb
.dlrowrednu eht fo tuo
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
.egde eht dehcaorppa eh sa gnitoof sih gnidnim
.etal taht tuo yats ot tnaw t'ndid uoy derugif tsuj I
,htlaeh ruoy rof dab si citsalp taht syas moM“
noisulli eht evig dluow taht gnihtemoS
,mih ot rewolf a tneserp enoemos dah reven d'eH
.gnihton s'tI"
peeK“   yojne esaelP
,htrof dna kcab mets sti detsiwt eH
"?gniod uoy era tahW—
seert fo eltsur eht raeh uoy nehw esolc er'uoy wonk uoY
etoyoC triD yB ”htaP eht ot
,em htiw tuo gnignah rof sknahT
.setunim erom wef a deklaw yeht sa tnelis tpek tub
,seye sih dellor tsuj nonreV dna
.thgir leef t'ndid taht tub ,deil nonreV
,rehtruf yna ti hcaorppa neht gnah taht tel rehtar dluow nonreV
”.daetsni eseht em sevig ehs os
.tsrub ot ydaer eb ot demees syawla nivlA
.eromyna gnihtyna gniwollof neve saw eh fi derednow eh
.elzzum sih dnuora wap a gnittup erofeb demialcxe nivlA "!skle-hcrib ehT
,yltcaf-fo-rettam derewsna eh erofeb ecaf sih no noisufnoc fo kool eniuneg a saw erehT
sehsub esoht dnoyeb gnihton saw ereht taht
.ni flesmih tog eh elkcip a saw yllaer siht ,kcuF
.mets sti fo kcen eht dna selpmet s'ti dnuora dedurtorp sniev dna stekcos tuo deglub seye tohsdoolB .maercs emoseurg a ni dexif htuom a saw edisnI
.ega ni revo dehcnuh lla
.mih saw ti taht depoh nonreV ,tsael tA
,ot kcab emoc uoy nehw enog eb ll'ehS
.diarfa saw eh wonk ot liat sih gnikorts nivlA ees ot deen t'ndid eH
",tsom ta ,sruoh wef a rof enog eb annog tsuj er'eW
.rehtruf tib a no deunitnoc yehT
.ddo tlef dessap yeht eert dna
.notrac draobdrac ynit a tuo gnillup ,kcap eht dehctans eH
.od ot dias murof eht tahw s'tahT ?tahW"
VI nedaJ kcapteJ fo esimorp eht tub
.dniw gnissap s'yellav eht ni yltfos derettulf dna
,deunitnoc etoyoc eht nehw ,revewoH
,koot eh pets yreve tuB
.remrahC eniuqE eht
.emoh gniog m'I dna niaga taht oD"
"?ereht ni ecam neve ereht sI
.tniap ron eiprahs ni nward t’nerew yehT
.spil sih morf esool tel psag tfos a
setunim wef a rof yltnelis ti deklaw htoB
.syawyna sbuc eht epacse ot tuo teg ot daH
,dias nonreV ",elttil a tsuJ"
,lward nrehtuos sih htiw nevE
.stniop tsehgih rieht ot dekrep srae dna deltsirb ruf ,pu tpael eH
,ti eciton ot tsrif saw nonreV
.detiucric trohs eh ekil epaga gnuh wam s’nivlA dna
.ngis eht fo kcab eht no dednal seye sih
y ta semag emos yalp nac ew ebyam ,haeY"
sburhs ynit eht revo deppets nonreV
.remrahC eniuqE eht
.uoy esruc ot sdoow eht fo tuo emoc ll'yeht ,eno yortsed uoy fi dna srewolf eseht tcetorp skle-hcrib eht taht dias tI"
.skle-hcrib eht ees annaw ew fi prahs peek attog eW
.ot mih gnitcerid saw nivlA tahw ees dluoc eh ,revo deklaw nonreV nehW
,bmud saw siht wenk eH .bmud saw sihT
.ereh morf syaw elttil a ylno s'tI"
.gninrom eht ni ylrae nus eht ni tuo ksab ot sdoow eht fo edisni eht morf yaw rieht ekam yehT
,deniamer secnartne dna sehcra eht ylnO
era uoy litnu kcab kool ton oD
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT no
.stnetnoc sti mih llet dluoc edisni gnihsols eht ot gninetsil fi sa ti koohs eh ,yldrazahpaH
.hannaH gnimmuH sa gniht hcus on t'nia erehT
***** .esuoh sih fo tuo deggard saw eh sa demialcxe lerriuqs eht
.gnitoof sih gnihctaw flah dna gninetsil flah
,nwot revo lla tuoba nwerts neeb dah egdirB mossolB fo sgnitniaP
,hgis a htiw dehsinif nivlA
,drawrof meht derehsu eh ,sedalb redluohs sih neewteb wap sih htiW
.derongi gninraw A .nekorb elur A .detaloiv oobat A
,sevael eht did sa
,sdaeh rieht morf gnidurtorp sreltna detsiwt emas esoht
.etoyoc eht morf ffocs a gnitteg
.edis s'nonreV ta klaw ot pu gnihctac ,dias eh
",mrots a gnirud tuo evag egdirB"
.eiprahs ni ysiad eht decafed dah enoemoS
.yad eno tuo evag tsuj dna
.tnesba yletelpmoc saw noitces elddim ehT
,gniunitnoc erofeb sdrow sih revo gnikniht ,deppots eH "—
.elzzum dinac gnol sih ssorca elims thgirb a
,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer
,hguoht dluoc eh fI
.seirrow sih esae pleh t’ndid ti ,hguoht ecnelis ni deklaw yeht sa nevE
.mih fo tnorf ni erom noillim a dah llits tub
lluks s’etoyoc eht tsniaga dedlof srae tsenraE
.draykcab sih ot tuo gnidael wodniw ssalg eht fo trohs sehcni saw eson siH
.driew dna diputs lla si siht fi neve
.devom gnihton tub
,eugra dluoc nivlA erofeB ".gnihtyna
.tniop yna ta ffo dik robhgien ypeerc eht llac dluoc eH
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
.etoyoc eht htiw kcits t'ndid taht tub
,elbisiv ylerab tsuj llits saw htap ehT
.tsol esoht fo yromem ni eseht detnalp skle-hcrib eht yas smurof ehT"
,erus t'nsaw nonreV
,loohcs hgih ni sroinuj htob erew yehT
.hsur a ni rood eht tuo mih deggut dna
.rood eht nepo gnuws eh sa tuo derepmihw nonreV ",ylrae er'uoY"
erew uoy thguoht I"
,ti naem t'ndid eH ".esuoh ruoy-
.etats nezorf sih fo tuo pans ot mih tog
,erofeb sa noitativni lufituaeb eht ni ton ,devaw yeht dna
.meht edistuo dlrow eht nefaed ot denord stcesnI
.hserf yltneloiv dekool noitcurtsed s’egakcerw eht
.syob eht htob deltrats dna
.emoh kcab yaw rieht dnif reve ll’yeht fi dna
,esor dna dewob sehcnarb riehT
,derepmihw nonreV "?nivlA-A"
.ysiad a pmots ot ydaer toob a evoba nettirw saw
.gnorw saw gnihtemos wenk eh
.daeha reep ot kcab sehsub eht deleep dna
.thginot rof hguone enif era skle-hcriB .on ,oN" .daeh sih koohs eh dna pu doots kcab s'nonreV no ruf ehT ".etal
.mih gniracs rof dab tlef eh nehw ekil tsuj thguoht ni deppord saw daeh s'nivlA
dik robhgien ypeerc eht gnieb morf tnew nivlA ,tnemom taht tA
.meht htiw deveiler noisnet rieht fi sa ,yletaidemmi denruter stcesni dna sdriB
,kcab dekool nonreV
?tog ev'uoy lla s'tahT ?ti s'tahT"
.daerd erup yb deppots saw etoyoc eht dna
.egdirb eht ot pu yaw eht lla teg dluow yeht litnu tsael tA
.egdirb eht ot revo dna srewolf eht dnoyeb dekool eh sa hguoht deppas saw ytiliuqnart eht llA
,tius dewollof nonreV
.yaw taht nivlA rof sgnileef dah eh kniht t'ndid eH
.tsum dnaldoow fo lrihw kciht a ni dednuorrus erew yeht litnu sesnes s'owt eht denepmad egailof kcihT
.tnemssarrabme htiw deretsulf ,kcaba nekat saw nivlA ".emoh
spit rieht ot pu doots srae htoB
.mih sdrawot tuo dleh ysiad a saw wap s'etoyoc eht nI
.mih pots ot tuo wap a gnihcaer
"?ngis eht s'erehW"
.sehsub eht hguorht ekorb eh litnu
,yltalf denialpxe eh sa kcab htob debbarg nonreV
.regnol dnoces a tiaw t'ndluoC"
.pirt trohs a saw siht taht ni llird ot gnitnaw
"?siht si neve tahW
,eid dna dlo worg srewolf eht nehW
.retaw meht hctef ot woleb klaw yeht
.nekops teg diasnu sdrow nehw teg syob taht tliug drawkwa taht gnileef
.htap eht pu deunitnoc yeht sa edis s’lerriuqs eht ta tpek dna
",yltnelis tuo seidob eht devom dna
,stih gnineve nehW
.gnikcap eht od ll'I ,emit txen ,eniF"
,noisnet s’etoyoc eht esae ot detnaw mih fo traP
,yrenecs eht gnitcepsni no desucof oot elttil a saw eH
:eil elttil a eb dluoc tI
.ffo hsurb ot dah yltnatsnoc eh sdees ylkcirp dna sgiwt htiw mih deggat yehT
,taht ekil mih ta gnippans dab tlef nonreV
.yrevocsid sih rof edirp fo ria na htiw ylsselerac gnola neddort tsuj nivlA
",driew ro diputs s'ti kniht t'nod I" ".driew
.eniuneg gnihtemos rof gud dna
edis s'etoyoc eht ta debbaj woble nA
.rehtruf yna og ot ton gninraw lanif a
.esimed rieht ot lialf d'yeht erofeb tnemom eht ni deppart reverof
,ffo flesmih tuc nonreV "—
.gnihton saw erehT
.thgin eht fo semit lla drayevarg eht nwod dna pu neeB
lerriuqs eht sdrawot kcab derats
,ees ot nivlA rof pu ti detfil eH
pu hctac lerriuqs eht gnittel
,burhs a otni thgiarts detrats nivlA
".uoy morf nelots d'ehs tahw gniwonk ton
,tuo derettups tsuj eh ,daetsnI
.rennid dehsinif I sa noos sa evael ot mom ym deksA
,ylsuovren mra sih debbur nivlA
dekcoc daeh s’nivlA ”.retaw s’tI“
.dewollof hsarc on tub
.ssarg dna trid eht tsniaga deggard ylpmil dna deggas liat siH
.thgis eht yb derutpac elihw sdrow eht dnif t'ndluoc tub
.stiartrop dna sepacsdnal ecitcarp ot stsitra gniddub rof tops suomaf ylralucitrap a
,no deunitnoc tsuj eh tub
,etoyoC triD yb ”2 fo 1 traP
,elims yfoog s'etoyoc eht rednu gnissap dnoces yreve htiW
etihw si ruf reH
.seert s’tserof eht otni tuo deohce dna elzzum sih fo tuo dehcnip kaeuqs dehctip hgih A
meht dniheb sdoow eht hguorht delpmart dniw fo tsug gninefaed kciht a
.llew sa edis rehto eht revo lla delwarcs neeb dah laocrahC
.gnisaet tsuj m'I"
.seisiad fo hctap eht ni derrits ladep elgnis a toN
.sreltna erew yehT
.ekops nivlA erofeb
.woleb egakcerw eht ees dluoc eh
.eson s'etoyoc eht htaenrednu thgir regnif a dleh dna dnuora nups eH
.wodniw eht morf yawa gnippets ,daeh sih koohs nonreV
.evaw gnimlac a otni sladep rieht deltsur
.tsrif drawrof pets ot mih nopu yal nedrub eht yltnerappa os
,nezorf saw nonreV ".ffilc
"!sruoh wef a rof enog eb ot gniog ylno er'eW"
.taht tsuj od ylisae dluoc ylbaborp eh
.edis eht ot gnikcoc elzzum
seisiad eht hguorht welb dniw fo tsug A
,saw ti sa tcnitsid ,tnecs A
liat sih yb neet rehto eht barg ot detnaw eH
,ereht ton er'yeht fI"
.ton ro srac eht ni erew elpoep fi
.esolc oot tog eh revenehw liat dna stnap s'nonreV gnihctac sdnah ekil tuo delwarps htworgrevO
!!!htaP eht ot peeK
.elims dellif-secarb a dehsalf eh sa noitcerid hcihw yreve ni delkceps thgiL
,meht ot nemhcriB eht denommus yllaer dah lautir s’nivlA fi woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
"?won tahw did ohW"
.edisa ti gnihsup
.gnol era sgnaf reh dna
htaeneb yellav eht morf gnituops dniW
.mih htiw pu hctac ot gnilggurts yltnatsnoc saw eh ekil tlef lerriuqs ehT
.sehcnarb t'nerew yeht
.lerriuqs eht naht reivaeh sdnuop ytnewt dna rellat toof a flah tuoba
.ruf sih ot kcuts tserof gnikcuf eht fo flah tuohtiw emoh nruter dluow eh yaw on eb d'erehT
,daeh sih koohs dna dehgis tsuj nivlA
?selggog noisiv thgin ,sessenrah ,sepor ,tik dia tsrif ,nug eralf eht s'erehW"
kcab eno gib nwo sih evag eH
!tsaeB ni derutaef saw htaP eht ot peeK
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dekrow yldrah tI
.nworgrevo saw ti fo hcum hguoht neve
,dellac nonreV "!pu tiaW !nivlA"
pu sgniht raelc ot mees t’ndid noitanalpxe ehT
.elbat yawecnartne eht tsniaga gninael ,denihw nonreV
.taht ees dluoc nivlA dna laer tub
.lamron dednuos taht yas ot gnihtemos tsuj saw tI
.sevren sih no teg ot gnitrats saw eh tub
.yawa daeh sih nrut erad t'ndid tub
.ylhsipeehs deilper lerriuqs eht
,toh si nus eht nehW
,niaga deirt eh ",yllaer ,mu ,oN"
.ecnatsid eht ni tuo sehcra nworb-der owt eht was dna
?noitnetta yna gniyap uoy t'nerA"
,desruc eb ton rehtar hcum d’I ,oslA
.lwoH notsruhT yb detide
.yad lla dnuora gnittis tsuj naht retteb s'ti tub
.redluohs eht yb mih debbarg nivlA nehw sehsub eht ot tsomla saw nonreV ".uoy
,dexelprep dekool nivlA
.sehcrib fo tserof kciht eht otni kool ot denrut sdaeh rieht ylnO
,ksud gnidaf eht fo thgil eht nI
.morf kcab deklaw tsuj d'yeht ffilc eht tuo doots gnitrap eht revo tsuJ
,sekips latem ot yletarepsed gnulc sknalp nedooW
eugra smurof ehT"
.syawyna tuo nur dah emit wonk mih tel llebrood eht morf zzub A
.thgirf ruoy esae ll'ti ,selims ehs nehW
,reve sa detsur dna nrow
,plug a koot tsuj eH .dluow rehtien
.hteet suorop dekoorc ni llif ot emit koot neve reziladnav ehT
a-a-A" .sehsub fo llaw a dehcaorppa yeht sa deksa eh
revo gnidnats nam dlo na ekil nwod gnirewolg
.sehsub owt neewteb tuo dekop daeh a
.ereht teg nac ew kniht t'nod I"
,hguoht tfig eht tpecca dluoc eh erofeB
.etteuorip a ni gnicnad sladep eht
.taeh ekil etoyoc eht fo ffo gnitaidar neeb dah
.lward erutangis sih ni detrats neve nivlA erofeb txen gnimoc saw tahw wenk nonreV
.denodnaba neeb dah tahw mialcer ot gnithgif
.degru nonreV ",emoh daeh s'teL"
.dluoc eh tseb sa sdnuos eht dewollof eH
,meht fo tnorf ni tsuj draeh eb dluoc doow gnidneb fo snaoM
,regral saw nivlA
,noitcepsni resolc nopu tub ,sdaeh rieht revo gnuh sehcnarB
ilimaf skool eert sihT ?tahW" "!nivlA"
rehtie sdneirf fo tol a evah t'nod I ,naem I"
,evom t'ndid eh fi tub
.erots ni sknarp erom yna dah nivlA esacni ecnatsid toof a gnipeek
.gnihtyna ro tsixe sesruc taht ton
,t'ndluow eh gnihsiw nonreV
.nonreV retfa gnisahc ,teef sih ot teg ot delbmarcs eH ".od
hguorht debmilc yeht burhs yrevE
.ssarg eht dna ,srewolf eht ,sehcnarb eht
.dnuorg eht ot wol deppid elzzum sih dna
,deilper eh ",gniht erus ,haeY"
.taht wenk nonreV tub
,etoyoc eht ot denrut ,deppots eH ".oot
,mra eht ffo werht eh dna
,drawrof deppets nonreV
.tniop yna ta eciohc trams eht ekam dluoc eh taht wenk dna
,rehtie taht tuoba doog gnileef ton ,dehgis eH ".yad
uoy htiw sgniht erom od ot ekil d'I dna
dehcnip sregnif sih
esae ta erom tlef eh
,dlo sedaced neeb ev’tsum ti hguohT
tnew eh gnola rehtruf eht reivaeh worg ot demees stnalp ehT
.noisufnoc ni delknirw tuons sih
.eurt t'nsaw taht wonk
,niaga dellac nonreV os
,tniop egatnav eht morF
,niar hguone ton s'ereht nehW
;thgirla saw gnihtyreve taht
,wols os sedirts gnol ni kcab klaw yeht
.egakcerw eht hguorht nar taht keerc eht ta nwod dekool nonreV
.eman reh t'nsi hannaH gnimmuH"
.dniheb tfel tog eh erofeb mih retfa hsur ot kciuq saw dna
.tuhs deppans dna nepo deppop wam sih semit lareveS
,laer ylniatrec saw htap ehT
.tsug a t'nsaw ti ,tpecxE
,mih ot taht yas ot detnaw eH
.nus gnidaf eht denekrad seert gnimooL
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb ”htaP eht ot peeK“
.meht fo owt eht dekcom taht eno tub
.ytuaeb war sti derutpac eno elgnis a ton gniwonk
.evaw a htiw resolc emoc ot mih gnitivni
nivlA ot denrut eH
.bmud kool tsuj d'eh
?siht od ot gniog ylsuoires ew erA"
.dnoces a neve rof nwod mih elttes ot tsuj llits mih dloh dna
.dellab swap sih htiw dias nivlA "!deticxe m'I"
.thgin eht rof ni yats ot ediced dluoc eh ,tniop yna tA
.peerc a dna tnereffid m'I kniht elpoep wonk I"
.derettuts nonreV ",nivlA-a-
.ksid wolley eht ni dehcteks ecaf a ees ot revo denael nonreV
.dniw on leef tub
.revo gnikat saw raef nehw edam serutaerc derruf lla taht hcnets a saw tI
"!egdirb eht fo pot eht ees nac uoy ,kooL
,yaw eht gnola lla mih thguof seert dna sehsuB
.ffuh a ni teef sih ot pu gnidnats
.esnopser on tog tub
.sredluohs sih deggurhs eh ,egdirb eht ot teg ot yaw elbisiv on saw ereht taht deveiler elttil a gnileeF
.plug a neewteb derettum nonreV
.emas eht lla reh llac yeht tahw s'tI
,tlef eh tahw dettimda eh fi dna yag t'nsaw eH
",em htiw ereh tuo gnimoc rof sknaht ,yeH"
.htap eht saw ti thguoht yeht ,tsael tA
neve t'nod ylbaborp yehT
.noitcerid s'egdirb eht sdrawot gnidniw liart a fo stnanmer ees dluoc eh ,ti fo tsom dih ssarg fo sehctap hguohT
.tsif sih ni rewolf eht dehsauqs nivlA
.eno hsiyob thgirb s'etoyoc eht ekil t'nsaw tI
.nonreV ot erom hcum os gnihtemos ot
.seye sih fo srenroc eht ta pu gnidliub meelg yretaw a tuo ekam dluoc eh
pu dekool nonreV
.thgis ruoy llud ll'ti ,sgnis ehs nehW
,yoc dna ,hsipeehs ,llams saw ti ,daetsnI
.emertxe tib a saw taht thguoht tsuj I
.ngis eht ni detniap seisiad wolley dna etihw emas esoht ni derevoc ffilc a ot yletaidemmi del gniraelc ehT .esolc neve toN
.tseug a sa mih gnimoclew erew yeht gnikniht ,delims nonreV
.ngis eht tsap tsuj detniop eh dna detfil elzzum s'nivlA
.ados dna azzip htiw deriap
.sag ekil detfaw ti dna
drawrof mih gniknay etoyoc eht yb trohs tuc saw nonreV "!yeH
.eno yb eno tuo dellup gnieb seidob delgnam detrotnoc rieht
.ot tuoba saw eh tahw yas ot detnaw eh erus ton
.ylsuoenatlumis meht morf desaeler hgis A
,evom ot sgel sih detloj eh
".deticxe tsuj m'I ,yrroS"
.liat sih gnisahc saw eh ekil dnuora gnilcric ,dias nivlA
.ecnad rieht nioj ot mih deggeb yeht fi sa nonreV ot gnivaw
,llits deniamer sehsub ehT
.nirg dinac yhtoot sih ni ylthgirb derekcilf secarB
,nrow saw draob nedoow ehT
,ees dluoc eh os sehsub eht kcab dellup dah nonreV
.enot sih ot ytirecnis tsenoh htiw saw ti
.sdneirf yna evah t'nod I
,krow ta reganam ym ebyam dna uoy naht rehto ,kceH
.ylesolc dniheb deliart nivlA dna
.elims a mih evag dna
.elzzum sih fo tnorf ni wap eht yawa dettaws nivlA
,flesmih tneiroer ot pots dluoc eh erofeb tsuJ
.sseldrager hguorht desserp eh tub
.ti htiw tnew evloser s'lerriuqs eht dna deppans tI
.noitalosed eht edih dluoc thgin erofeb ni lla ti gnikat
",nwod yaw eht lla seog nus eht erofeb egdirB mossolB ot gniog teg retteb eW
.dedeen yletarepsed eh ria hserf fo tib yhtlaeh eht saw siht ,gnihtyna fI
.krof eht ot kcab wollof ot meht rof hguone ysae tub
.eye eht fo kcirt a tsuj s'ti kniht uoy
.elims a otni nworf sih gnisrever erofeb sraet yna kcab gnicrof ,daeh sih koohs nivlA
.ti teg t'nod I" .eson s'etoyoc eht fo tnorf ni thgir
,levon a gnitirw si
"?esle enoyreve ekil hgih teg tsuj ew t'nac yhW
.rae nommoc eht ot elbigilletninu snaom gnol ni kaeps yehT
—ffo nur t'noD" "!tuo ti kcehC"
.ecnartne s'egdirb eht morf yawa tfel ylprahs dereev htap ehT
.dnoces a rof snoitome sih pu dexim tsuj thgiliwt dna gnittes ehT
.gab eht edisni keep ot ni gninael ,deksa etoyoc eht
.pmats gnihsurc elbativeni eht ecarb ot dehcaertuo smra fael elituf ,revo deldduh saw rewolf ehT
,egdirb eht no tseretni fo gnihtemos was eh ekil kool ti ekam ot deirt eH
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.sniamer rieht gniruoved thguac hteet ekil
,egdirB mossolB demool daehrevO
.sevael dlog remmus rieht ni gninoows seert hcrib eht doots gnicnef dekcnalp allinav citsalp eht revo tsuJ
dluow eH .rood txen devil yllacitcarp eh ,tihs lleW .ylrae noitacav rieht morf emoh gnimoc erew stnerap sih taht yas tsuj ylbaborP .kaew eb d’taht ,haN .dab gnihtemos eta
.elgnad sgel sih tel ot taes a gnikat dna edisffilc eht ot gnippets ,detrats nivlA
.sesnes eht sllud anaujiraM"
.nwad dna ksud gnirud meht ees ylno nac uoy taht syas murof ehT"
.drayevarg eht ni hannaH gnimmuH rof kool syawla dluoc ew
lwocs a otni depraw elzzum s'nonreV ".hannaH
,riaf mees t'ndid tI
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR  .setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoC triD wolloF
?gnihtyreve tog uoY"
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.ot dehsinav dah ti fo tser eht erehw deulc sliar tneb drawnwoD
,htaP eht ot peeK“
.tsrubtuo eht yb deltrats ,daehrevo derettulf sdriB
,hguoht htap eht fo daetsnI
htiw nigeb ot noitacol a fo laedi taht reven saw egdirb ehT"
,nem erom nezod A
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ti tuoba gnikniht ,lleW
,driew elttil a s'ti ,naem I"
.edisni kcab notrac eht gniffuts erofeb
.snoisiced sih gninoitseuq dna detnalp gniyats ,desufer eH
.tuo ti detniop nivlA litnu
,god.ecioveht ta
?dab os meht ees ot tnaw uoy od yhW
,detuohs nonreV "!lleh eht tahW"
.ti ekat ot wap a tfil ot elbanu
.serutcip dna sdrow eht dnuora kcalb eht saw ngis eht tuoba railucep tsoM
espalloc eht fo drocer elttil yrev s'erehT
,woleb maerts eht otni lla meht ssot d'eh
.yad lla ffo gnikrej dna semag oediv gniyalp kaerb remmus sih dneps tsuj t'ndluoc eH
.dog detsur a ot yrolg gnisiarp selpeets hcruhc ekil seert eht evoba enola doots yehT
,kcab nrut ot seitinutroppo noillim a detsaw ydaerla d’eH
.deneppah neve evah ton thgim taht gnihtemos ni pu thguac os teg flesmih tel eh taht dehsulf elttil a
.tuhs htuom sih tpek elzzum s'nivlA no noisserpxe tsenrae eht gniees tub
ro derit gnileef saw eh
"?ereht ton er'yeht fi tahW"
.troper evissam a tnarraw ot laed hguone gib a t'nsaw ti esuaceb s'taht yas emos dna
.kcab s'nonreV deppals dna dehgual nivlA
.edis eht ta gnidnats ngis enol a emac ni elim flah a tuobA
,dias eh ",keep a ekaT"
.tserof eht hguorht yaw sih gnigdurt etoyoc eht raeh dluoc eh ,daehA
,llorts sih desuap nivlA
.taht ta degnirc ecaf s'nonreV ".skle-
nonreV fo dloh debbarg eh ,taht htiW ".gnikcap
skcor deggaj tsgnoma woleb derettacs yal sdraob deretnilps dna skcart norI
,yawa nrut ot dah nonreV
ti no regnif sih tup etiuq t'ndluoc eH
.ssenredliw eht otni tuo gniyarts htiw elbatrofmocnu
.tserof eht ni sretsnom erew ereht taht eveileb yllautca ot dlo oot yaw
.dnoces a rof rednaw ezag sih gnittel
,deppots saw etoyoc ehT
hguorht deppets nonreV
.dnuora ti dehctiws eh taht emit yreve ffo dna no deppilf enohp sih fo neercs ehT
.htap eht revo gnidraug nem dedahs fo ecnalbmes eht evig ot ssorca deggard neeb dah laocrahc ,daetsnI
.edisni ygrene sih thguorb etoyoc eganeet eht sa kcab dekconk ylraen saw nonreV ".syawyna
.ffilc eht ot efil wen gnirb dna meht tnalper yeht
.noisnam eht ni rood dekcol elgnis eht nepo ton oD
.wap ykahs s’nonreV revo selcric ni deppilf enohptrams ehT  )2 fo 1 traP(
.lla fo noitibihorp tsedlo eht spahrep ,noitatneserp ruo ot ralutit dnA .egdelwonk fo tiurf eht fo tae ton oD
.thgilhsalf a dna esoht era gnignirb m’I llA"
.roolf eht no gnittis kcap llams a deggans dna nwod dehcaer nonreV ,hgis a htiW
:saw ti tahw neht thgir wenk eh dna
hguoht ria thguac ylno eH
.dedaf dna deppihc tniap
pu ti derevoc daorliar eht taht yas srehtO
,tuo dellac nivlA "!nonreV"
deldnah gnieb tuoba nialpmoc ot ydaer saw eH
.sgniraeb sih hctac dna yrt ot tserof eht ta dnuora gnikool
.yldiputs eugnot sih ffo deliart sdrow ehT "—
tniop eno ta dna
aw rehto eht sdael htap ehT
,gniht gnorw eht dias eh wenk eH
.yob rehtona ssel hcum
,nivlA ot kcab denrut eh nehW
llits deniamer ruf riehT
.rehto hcae otni dehsams dna dehcnurc srac xob deitpme doots elbbur eht potA
.sdoow eht ni tsol gnitteg dna ffo gninnur morf sbuc eht peek ot elat taht dlot ylno stneraP
,stibbar fo sesproc derutcip eH
,etoy regae eht dniheb deliart nonreV ".eye
.drow a tuo tel ot dehcnelc oot saw taorht s'enoemos nehw tuo ekops taht llems taht saw tI
,htaed sti sdrawot gnilbmut eert a ekil gnol tuo dehcterts tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tnew yeht rehtruf eht htap eht ot resolc tperc tserof ehT ".thginot
.egde retuo eht revo demool serugif detagnole kraD
.denodnaba neeb dah eh taht ees ot denrut dna
sredluohs sih deggurhs nonreV
;wolf ydaets s'retaw eht yb pmil yawa deirrac gnieb flesmih ekil
,pu tnew srae s'nivlA