.ffo ti hsup ot elba erew rehtien tub
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
,esolc dekool dah etoyoc eht fo tsoM
.ylgninetaerht sevael sti gniltsirb
.eno elgnis yreve otni gnikcams swap sih
.epacse fo htap sih dekcolb taht lufdnah a tub
,drawrof dehsad nonreV
.hcnarb eert a yb elkna sih morf detsioh
,daeh sih koohs eH
.ylthgit tsehc sih gnidloh dna htaerb rof gnilggurts
dnaherofeb klat ot deirt yeht emit ynA
.yaw eno gninael eert a revo dehcnuh sehcnarb dniheb dehsinav eH
elims a ni kcuts saw eh litnu
,edis sih ta pu emac eH
dehca evom yreve sti fi sa niap saw
.hcrib rehto yna morf elbahsiugnitsidni delgnim krab etihw dna sevael wolley rieht litnu detrotsid dna depraw yeht
.erugif sih fo tser eht tuo ekam neve t’ndluoc eh taht liat s’yob rehto eht no desucof os seye
mih htiw gninnips saw tserof eht ekil tlef tI
.sredluohs eht ta thgir ffo kaerb ot ydaer
,drawkcab delbmuts nonreV
”?seigrella lanosaes htiw em desruc uoY !seigrellA“
.nivlA fo tser eht sdrawot pu ylwols gninrut daeh dna seye
,og ot mih detnaw tserof eht erehw saw taht fI
.noisiv sih fo segde eht deniltuo kcalB
.emac reven eh tub
,egailof eht hguorht decar eh sa oga dnoces a tsuj duol os demees yeht hguoht ,spetstoof s’nivlA nevE
,pruls gninekcis tew a htiW
.tserof eht ni tsaeb eht htiw enola dna deracs
,ssarg eht ssorca dellor snroca ehT
,hguoht erutnevda na fo daetsnI
,denrut dna deggurhs kle-hcrib ehT
,ehcadaeh sih htiw yggof oot dnim sih
”,esruc eht si siht kniht I
,ffo mih hsup ot detnaw eH
;etoyoc eht ot pu gnihctac eb d’eh dnoces enO
.etisoppo gniklaw ,decaf-tuoba dna kcab denrut eH ".pu dexim tog eW"
.wam nepo-reve sti hguorht gnippils dum derevoc mrow fo spord
.gel sih no yvaeh gnidnal mra sti htiw despalloc ydob eritne s'ti
.stonk tpmeknu ni rehtegot gnipmulc
,esle gnihtemos ro cigam yb rehtehW
mih dniheb morf tuB
.htaeneb trid eht otni gnihsalps ,sedis s'ti morf tuo detsrub seitisnetnI
eulg htiw gniddehs deldnub dah enoemos ekil
emos ni sdrow erew edam ti snaom eht taht won raeh dluoc nonreV
niaga pu gnippoh erofeb ruf sih fo tuo trid dna ssarg gnihsurb
,noitats sag eht morf gniklaw woN
.tsaeb eht retfa gnisahc dna sruof lla no pu gnilwarc
taorht sih ni erehwemos kcuts demees ti fo llA
”htaP eht ot peeK“
.flesmih dnuora epocs ot thgir dna tfel detfihs eh dna
,rehtegot tnemom tsal rieht eb dluow siht fi taht gniwonk
.tsehc sih no ti htiw htaerb sih gnihctac elbuort gnivah saw nonreV
,meht dniheb ffilc eht dnif ot dekcohs ton saw nonreV .niaga
.meht sdrawot nwod kcab gnimoc mra nedoow sti fo hcnurc elbativeni eht rof gniraperp dna
.noitcerid rehto eht ni saw nivlA ylerus neht
deppop yllanif srae s’nonreV
,noziroh eht revo thgir dna tfel edils ot demees nus gniyd eht nevE
,ti thgif ot dah nonreV
.meht fo owt eht neewteb shguoc dna sezeens derdnuh a yb detpurretni saw
,won yb semit nezod a etoyoc eht ot ti denialpxe d’eh erus ytterp
.gnitiaw egdirb dna seisiad eht htiw
,pu denepo tsehc s'ti fo traP
.sdaeh rieht ni dekram saw trid fo hctap yreve dna ,ssarg fo edalb yreve ,kcor yrevE
.sgel sih neewteb dekcut liat dna
.edis sih no gninrut
,gniyas erofeb dnuora yaw eht lla denrut etoyoc eht litnu gnitiaw
,nwod mih pleh dna
.ni gnittes eiree eht nepmad ot gnipoh ,dehgual nonreV
.selbbub ynit ni tuo gnisaeler ,taorht sih ni dnuora delbbob bos dekohc A
.mih fo edis rehtie no wol gnuh smra sih dna
,raeppaer ot etoyoc eht detcepxe eh erehw ot dekool nonreV
.srieht evoba tsuj saw elzzum ekil-lluks eht litnu gnidneb sgel detoor s’ti
.htaerb sih hctac dna nwod wols ot elba eh saw
.meht fo rehtie ot emac mrah on tub
mih ot hsur ot ydaer saw eH
.dnuos gnippop lufwa na htiw gnidnal
.hguoht seye eht gnicalper on saw erehT
sehsub fo llaw taht ta kcab saw eh
.noitnetta sih thguac hsiws a
.nwod meht peek ot
",thgir t'nsi sihT"
,tniop egatnav sih morF
.retrofmoc eulb sih fo mirt nedlog eht tuo ekam dluoc eh taht hguone esolc ,esolc saw tI
.ssarg fo stekcop dna sevael dehsurc rednu derrulb
!tsaeB ni derutaef saw htaP eht ot peeK
,nuf fo tol a dah eh dias eh fI
,laer erew wenk eh kle-
,pu kool neve ot diarfa saw eH
.regnol yna ti raeb t’ndluoc eH
.meht ta krad gnihtemos gnitaeper saw ti llet dluoc eh
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sdrow dekciw sti gninaom regnol on tub ,lwocs sti ni llits
deggard liat siH
.cinap nwo sih yb deggof yromem yzah a gnimoceb saw eniltuo eugav stI
.diasnu tfel gnihtyna tnaw t’ndid yeht
.sdoow eht otni dednelb sevlesmeht serutaerc eht tub
.tserof eht hguorht dliw gninnur teef sih ot pu saw eh ,hsalf a nI
,tuo emac seye htoB
.wodniw moordeb sih saw
,esool dekool thgir ehT
,yawa gnirettulf sdrib eht tsgnoma evoba hgih esor ti
,tserof eht si edistuo tuB
,esrow ro ,htrae pu gud ot ralimis ,mih htaeneb hserf dna dloc lla saw tI
.seotatop fo kcas a ekil dnuorg eht otno mih deppord dah erutaerc eht ees ot denrut nonreV
,hguoht nwod edispu nivlA ees ot gninethgirf elttil a saw tI
.ti eb ot gniog saw siht ekil dekool ti tub
.ezeehw ypsar a ekil tuo gnimoc
,noisseccus dipar ni tuo emac sezeenS
.tons nwo sih ni swap sih gniykcits
.kcab mih dloh meht tel t'ndid eh tub
,tuo derettups eh ,buc gnirewoc a ekiL
,niaga mih gnihsup fo daetsnI
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dekohc lerriuqs ehT
.ees ot nonreV rof yleerf derab hteet talf yenob s’ti
smunrets debbaj rieht ta debbur dna decniw yehT
thgilhsalf eht tuo gnissot ,kcap s’nonreV otni regnif dehcnarb sti demrow ti ,daetsnI
.sleeh sih no htrof dna kcab kcor ylno dluoc eh dna
.tnemevom diulf gnol a ni denrut eert eht sa strap laudividni ni tib yb tib rehtegot dekcilc seceip wasgiJ
.mih retfa gnisahc ,deirc nonreV
.daed nonreV deppots taht etihw fo revils a gnilaever
”htaP eht ot peeK“   yojne esaelP
,levon a gnitirw si
,was eh lla derevoc yerg fo ezah A
.edis eht morf weiv otni emac tuons enivrec gnol A
.stnap dna trihs sih fo sroloc eht dekcimim taht kcum dna dum dna sevael tsuJ
.mra sih fo ruf eht otno thgir knug fo sgnirts gnol ffo depiw eh sa emas eht dekool nivlA
.slatep s’rewolf eht pota yltcerid tnuoma llams a tuo deruop ti
.stekcop sih htob ni swap sih htiw don elgnis a evag eH
ylwols deraeppa tI
",dnuora denrut tog ew sseug ,mu ,I"
.stsehc eht no drah meht fo htob gniddorp erofeb wap s’nonreV otni kcab sniamer s’notrac eht deppals ti ,ylbicroF
.teerts rieht ot renroc eht denrut yeht sa ados sih gnihsinif ,deksa nivlA
.gniraew esuoh eht tfel dah eh taht sehtolc eht yllautca t’nerew sehtolc sih ekiL
.tohsdoolb dna deniap seye
”!ereh fo tuo teG !yawa nuR !nonreV“
.sreltna derugifsid ekil daeh sti fo tuo yldekciw gnidurtorp sehcnarB
”.uoy ees ll’I sseug I ,thgirlA“
.evarg a fo mottob eht ta gnittis saw eh fi sa
.nivlA no gnisucof erofeb niaga sgnul sih gnillif ,depsag eH
.tserof eht otni kcab yaw rieht dedlof egde s’ffilc eht morf tsehtruf kle-hcrib ehT ”!esaelP
mih gniromuh tub
—OOHCA —kniht I“ .ees ot gnitsugsid saw tI
,ni denael knurt ehT
ecaf eritne sih devruc tI
,sregnif detsiwt dna emarf egral sti htiw neve ,evitnettA
.htap eht ot
.mih ot wap gnilbmert a tuo dehcaer ti
”!oohcA“ .mih tih ti nehw ffo nur dna pu dnats ot ydaer tuoba saw eH
.thgiliwt gniyd s’nus eht ni
.mih fo daeha syaw elttil a tsuj weiv otni emac liat derruf nat dna nworb s’nivlA
,flesmih htiw tsenoh gnieb saw eh fI
.ffilc eht morf trid erom pu dellup rehto eht sa tsuj dnuorg eht otni gniraeppasid toof detoor s’ti
.htaenrednu sbir gnisopxe
.ti morf noitnetta sih denrut eh emit hcae mih sdrawot gnipeerc neeb dah eert hcrib a raews dluoc eh ,semit lareveS
.oga sruoh tsuj gnidnats neeb d'eh erehw ees dluoc eh
.taht tuoba wonk t’ndid nonreV
reniatnoc eht fo flah pot eht ffo deppir ti
.llup eht rednu gnippir erofeb
,eid ot ydaer t’nsaw eH
.worb sti htaeneb stip sseleye eht edisni peed deworrub stekcos neknus kcalB
.thguoht a ylno sa tuo emoc t'ndid tahT .tiaW
.drawkwa saw siht ,doG
.yduolc sa tsuj werg dnim sih dna
.mih dniheb drah gnihtemos otni gnikconk yletaidemmi
htrof dna kcab gnitsiwt daeh sti fo edisni meht gnidloh sgnirts eht
,detutitsbus snroca owT
,mraw dna tsiom tlef sregnif sih neewteb ruf ehT
.ylitsah rehtegot nivlA deceip dah buc emos ekil
;gnissim erew sreksihw sih nevE
.hguone llew gnihctam sehtolc dna roloc ruf eht
,drawrof etunim a ylno gniklaw retfa ,hguone eurt dnA
,meht ta derats tI
,mih sdrawot daeh sih denrut etoyoc ehT .derepsihw nonreV ”?nivlA-A“
.edistuo ssenkrad eht si ,snoisserpxe erem
.yrros m'I ,tiaw ,nivlA" .sdeeps kcenkaerb ta gninnur sdoow eht otni ffo detrad nivlA erofeb ,koot ti lla s'taht ,elffins enO
.ti morf teef elpuoc a dah eh taht won guls depmots a ekil erom dekool liat s’nivlA
.mih ot resolc tog ti sa erats tub gnihtyna od ot dekcohs oot saw yob ehT
.levarg eciov sih ,nrets erew sdrow s'nonreV ".detartsurf
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT no
.negyxo rof dekohc nonreV dna ecno ta ffo emac thgiew eht lla ,ylnedduS
.esrow hcum os tlef siht esuaceb
.ffilc eht morf yawa gniklaw neeb d’yeht taht niatrec
,drawrof dehcaer dah lerriuqs ehT
,ffo deppord mra nA
.woleb yellav eht ni peed dnuora dellor ti dna
sliat dna ,srae ,ruf dellup yeht sa tuo derettihc spiy dna stnurG
,emit tsaL  ?yas nac ohw
,detacolsid dekool edis thgir dna tfel sih no delgnad taht smra ehT
”?htnom a tnaem ti kniht uoy oS“
.mih fo tnorf ni saw ti lleh eht revetahw rO
,htuom sih fo tuo denaorg ha ykahs a ylnO
,pu dnats dluoc rehtie erofeb dna
.detsisrep nivlA tub
,ruf sih fo hcni yreve nwod dehgiew srekcits dna sgiwT
,rehto hcae tsniaga delggurts owt ehT
.dneirf sih nodnaba tsuj t’ndluoc eh
,dnoces a rof mih fo tnorf ni doots nivlA
hctoocs yreve htiw seohs sih htaeneb depmulc trid tfoS
.slirtson rieht nwod gnippird tons eht yawa gnipiw llits elihw
,nonreV dniheb deirrulf spets derettiks nivlA
,tnemeticxe eht lla htiW
.niaga sehsub emas esoht otni thgir nar htob yeht nehw gnippots ylno
,detuohs dna kcab daeh sih werht eh
.ti pots ot tuo smra sih gnidaerps
,dehcaorppa eh sa ylkciuq sa tsuJ
.delffins eh hcum woh rettam on tecuaf a ekil gniytpme saw eson siH
.ffo saw etoyoc eht fo erom eciton eh did desucof ylurt eh nehw ylno tub
.eciov ypsar a ni dias ti ",nonreV"
”—ffo nur t’nod ,nivlA“
,nonreV ot pets a koot erutaerc ehT
.daor eht nwod tsuj devil taht etoyoc eht esuaceb tub
:esle gnihtyreve sa stiart emas eht derahs elzzum dinac rednels siH
hw-W“ .nwo sih fo ezeens tew yrev a
.tuo dekop sbmil eht erehw rednu tsuj gnilaever ecaf eht sa duol sa etiuq dednuos gnihton tub
?stnalp eseht retaw ot su tnaw uoY“ ,gniksa
.seisiad eht fo eno evoba gninepo eht gnuh dna
,depsag dna dehguoc eH
.elcsum dna senob no ti kcuts dna
”!keew txen emit emaS“
.lwoH notsruhT yb detide
.emit erom eno ti gnivarb dna
taht ylisae os ydob sih ffo deppir tI
,erolklof yb demaerdnu ,ecneics yb derevocsidnu tey ereht krul yam sregnad tahw dna ,thgin eht dna
,ereht tuo llits saw eH
,revocer ot tsrif saw nivlA
,reduol dna reduol gnitnahC
.gnitiaw yal egdirb ehT
,stsif otni ylthgit dezeeuqs swaP
,drawrof pets a ekat ot deirt tI "?nivlA"
.tserof eht otni ylduol gniohce ohce
.niaga ot tnaw dluow eh fi wonk t’ndid eh ,ylknarf esuaceb
,mih fo ffo deleep lla tI
.ksuh retuo s’hcrib a fo krab gnippihc
.trihs s’rehto eht fo stnorf eht otni seigolopa dna ,tons ,sraet deruop hcaE
",taht naem t'ndid I
owt eht neewteb gnihsup erofeb
.evom a ekam ro kaeps ot meht no gnitiaw saw ti ekil
.mih ot tsol yletelpmoc noitcerid fo esnes yna
retceps a fo sregnif ekil drawtuo dnetxe ot mees swodahs kcalb s’egdirB mossolB
,detuohs nivlA ,sgnul sih fo pot eht tA
detniop kle-hcrib eht erehw saw tahT
.draykcab sih fo gnicnef eht demrof taht sknalp allinav citsalp eht doots
,dneirf sih saw mih morf yawa gnicaf gniht siht taht demaercs gnihtyrevE
"!nivlA" .selcric ni gninrut
,htap sti ffo tuc nonreV
sniatnuom eht dniheb yawa dewots yllanif nus eht nehw dessim d’yeht
,raet gninekcis a htiW
.ecaf evarb a no tup dna daeh sih koohs eh
.mih dniheb sdray evif doog a eb d’eh ,txen eht
.edam eh sdrawkcab
.dereviuq pil mottob sih dna seye sih ni pu dellews truH
yrots s’thginoT dna
,dluoc llits eh elihw yawa klaw ot
.sdrawkcab dellup nonreV
.kcals gnignah wam htiw wap sih ni liat eht ta gnirats
neeb evah dluow ruf erehW
,thgil dna ,ytefas si edisnI
,nemhcrib eht doots meht evobA
teef derdnuh wef a naht sseL
!OOHCA !em ot siht od tsuj t’nac uoY !OOHCA !pots ,tiaW“
.emoserit werg erutaerc eht litnu
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.sraet yawa gnipiw dna gnizeens kcuts erew syob htoB
,ylsseltroffe thgir dna tfel gnuws nivlA
.peerc diputs uoy ,wonk I ".tsol er'eW"
.teknalb gnineve ylrae sti ni depparw llits noom eht delievnu daehrevo tsuJ
.yawa ti bur t’ndluoc eh tub
,selbmar elbigilletninu dehsur erew sdrow riehT
.ecno ta trapa emac ti fo lla dna
.yks eht otni pu gnihcaer yb
.taorht gnihctulc sih hguorht thgif dluoc taht ria elttil eht htiw deniarts sgnul siH
tsehc rieht ot desserp erew sehcnarb
,gnillaf dna gnitfil seert eht fo stoor eht raeh dluoc nonreV
.dehsinif krow rieht
.enog yletelpmoc erew
,htiw nigeb ot nosrep evarb yrev a t’nsaw eh dna
.sregnif nekorb detsiwt ekil tuo dna ni delruc sehcnarb eht sa
reilrae ereht gnieb eert a rebmemer t’ndid eH
.meht morf yawa klaw ot detrats oot ti tub
.muinarc sih tsniaga ylsuoiruf gnidnuop saw niarb sih dna dehca taorht sih ta gnihctarcs A
.pal s'nonreV otni thgiarts gnillor
,tuo deirc eh "!nivlA" .eromyna gninnur eb ot desoppus saw eh noitcerid hcihw erus neve ton ,dewols nonreV
,htrof dna kcab kcor yreve htiW
.syawyna ti mrifnoc ot gnideen tub ,dneirf sih t’nsaw ti llew lluf gniwonk ,ecaf sti otni pu dekool eH .mih gnicaf saw ti litnu delaever eb dluow mrof sti fo erom
,kcen sih pu denrub taeH
.sdaeh rieht fo kcab eht tsniaga dedlof srae ,sehsub eht fo egde eht ta doots htoB  )2 fo
,hguone esolc tog ti sa noos sA
,rehtegot emac ti nehw tub
,nehw on saw erehT
,sredluohs s'ti ffo delppot daeh ehT
,seert eht tsniaga decnuob peerC
.kle na fo lluks dehsilop a ekil dekool roiretxe s’erutaerc eht fo llehs drah ehT
,etsap otni mih denrut tsuj dah nemhcrib eht hsiw ot gninnigeb saw nonreV
,deniamer meht desruc taht eno eht ylnO
.steloiv dna ,sder ,segnaro ylno gnivael
.srae lerriuqs ytniop sih fo spit eht ot thgir detekcoryks dna ,skeehc sih otni
,eno tsuj toN .stsaeb nam-flah eert-
.gel sti tsniaga egduls a ni gnilbmurc
,peelsa llaf dluow eh erofeb ssap dluow sruoH
.stekcos dewolloh edisni deffuts
,niaga tuo og dluow yeht fI
.tuo deirc nivlA dna ,duht A
erom setunim dna
.spalp yppols ni dnuorg eht otno deppird ti fo seceiP
.tsaeb evissam eht morf troffe on tsomla htiw edisa deppals saw lerriuqs elttil ehT
.tihs oN .derettum nivlA
.emahs ot s’nivlA tup dluoc taht
.niaga delbmum nivlA
niaga sgel sih leef dluoc nonreV erofeb setunim ekat dluow tI
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.nemhcriB eht sa nwonk stsaeb nwod gnikcart erew nivlA dna nonreV
,ni gnikcik senimatsihitna eht htiW
”,gninnur pots seson ruo litnu ti gniod peek tsuj ylbaborp dluohs ew tub ,os kniht I“
,drah dehsarc yehT
.smra sih tfil neve dluoc nonreV naht retsaf guh thgit a ni mih decarbme dah nivlA
tnemevom neddus eht ta gnizeerf htob ,kcab dellup tI
.emas eht lla deerga tub
,deretnilps dna deppihc saw edam ti naom ehT
.ffo emac tsuj gniht eritne eht
,daetsni tuo dekohc dna
.dnuorg eht sdrawot ylmrif erew selzzuM
,thguoht a ot taht tpek nonreV
.spil sih no thgir kcep a yb dilos denrut saw tub
.elcsum nrot dna senob elttirb
,edis eno ot llul daeh sti was eh neht dnA
,nwod dna pu deddon eH
,ti fo ffo gnippird emac sehtolc sti fo strap eroM
era srehto lla hcihw fo ,raef tsedlo eht spahreP
.detartsurf er'ew dna krad gnitteg s'tI
.snotrac retaw draobdrac eht fo eno tuo gnillup erofeb
.rood eht nepo dluoc eh erofeb
.stsehc ekil-knurt rieht morf gnittuj yrc gnilwoh emas eht edam meht fo llA
,nepo dekcarc seert neewteb gnireep A
.dezeens nonreV
,weiv otni deppop dah srats tsethgirb ehT
.mih koops ot desu kcirt ro knarp a tub
,gnimialcxe erofeb tnih eht gnikat ylwols
.dluohs ti ekil tup yats ot elbanu demees mih gnidnuorrus noitategev eht llA
.esuoh nwo sih fo noitcerid eht ni gnidaeh dna kcab gninrut
.yawa rehtruf yltnacifingis nivlA ekat ot demees nrut dna evrews yrevE
.stoor nworb tew lufwa ni htrae eht pu dellup sgeL
.rehtie ysae ti gnikam t’nsaw nivlA
,sdrawkcab llef nonreV
.niaga ecno raeh yllautca dluoc eh dna
.desufnoc tog tsuj eW"
hcrib eht tuoba deirrow saw eh esuaceb ton
ohce llits ti raeh dluoc nonreV ,oN
,seceip ot gnillaf yllaretil ti etipseD
.sehsub dna seert dniheb kcud liat nworb eht dehctaw eH
,dnim sih esol ylurt dluoc eh erofeB
.esuoh sih sdrawot kcab gnippiks ydaerla ,enog saw eh
.dnuorg eht otni knis ot nageb yeht litnu
,ti fo tuo flesmih pans ot daeh sih ekahs ot dah nivlA
.ffilc eht etisoppo deklaw dna denrut htob yehT
,liaw gnol a tuo tel dna mih revo derewot ti
,ythgim gnihtemos dehcti seye siH
rettiwT no etoyoC triD wolloF
.meht edam evah ohw ew si ti esuaceb wonk ew sgniht eht lla dna
,hguoht ni gnihtaerB
.did eh dalg saw nonreV dna ,ffo flesmih tuc eh ”—fo tol a dah I
.yawa mih llup dna yrt ot redluohs sih dnuora mra na gnipparw
,tuo dils ti ,wam s'ti denepo ot deirt ti nehw dna
.dat a gnilkcuhc ,dias nonreV
flah eht fo rehtona ees ot ylno dnuora gnurps eH
.yawklaw s’lerriuqs eht ot pu denrut yeht sa tsuj dias nivlA
tuo tel eh erofeb selahni prahs eerht koot nivlA
.ecneirepxe gniworrah eht retfa
,yltnelis yawa gnihtyreve degolatac yehT
lwoh gnillihc s’ti nI
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR  .setadpu erutuf rof
.nivlA fo maercs tnatsid eht draeh eh raews dluoc eh
.remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb ”thgilyaD eht fo sretsnoM“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.meht dnuof evah nemhcriB eht spahrep tub
.taht ekil pu dedne evah dluoc nivlA woh aedi on dah yletinifed eh dna
.deksa nonreV ”?siht si tahw-
derewsna tI ”?gnol woh roF
.selkraps mid ni yks eht gnirettil
.knurt s’eert eht morf gninaorg gnol a yb detlah saw tub
,yna dnif t’ndid yehT
.kcab deknay dna liat sih fo toor eht yb mih gnibbarg
.ecalp tsrif eht ni etoyoc eht htiw tuo enog reven evah dluow nosrep trams A
.pleh fo sdaelp elgrug ylno dluoc ti ,waj a tuohtiW
.tserof eht gnivael ecnis noitasrevnoc laer a evah yllanif dluoc yeht
,emas eht gniod saw nivlA
,rehtegot nwod emac seenk s'ti fo htoB
.remrahC eniuqE eht
,shtrof dna kcab ynit ni teef sti gnilffuhS
,ecarbme rieht detpurretni pmots gnikluh A
.drawrof deppets dah erutaerc eht ees ot gninrut htob
.yob dinac eganeet a fo ffo gnimoc saw ti nehw raef naht esrow yaw knuts ssendas fo hcnets ehT
.ecaf sreganeet rehto eht otni thgir sgniht maercs rehtar d’eh
peek d'yeht emit siht
,ffo mih werht nonreV
,mra doog eno s'ti htiW
,derumrum nivlA ”,yako ,hO“
.nodnet a morf gnignah dna edis eno ot gnigniws ,dehcated waj ehT
.stekcos eye sih otni smlap sih depiw eh sa dias nivlA
.dinhcara suortsnom a fo bmil elgnis a lla saw ti deirrow
.mih pals yllautca thgim eh
,dias dna ,llew sa flesmih ot taht tpek eH .ylsuoivbO
”.og ti tel tsuj ,nonreV“
2 traP( etoyoC triD yB
”?keew txen esle gnihtemos od ll’ew ebyaM“
,enog saw htap ehT
.nivlA ot yas ot detnaw eh taht erus saw eh taht sgniht fo tol a erew erehT
,dekaerc ti fo trap yrevE
.won emoh daeh ll’I sseug I“
***** .sdoow eht otni gniraeppasid dna
.nonreV htiw ecaf ot ecaf gnimoc saw ti litnu dnuora detator ti
.dnuorg eht ot htob meht dekconk dna mra sti gnuws kle-hcrib ehT
.ecaf sih fo sedis eht otni dellird seloh ynit tsuj
meht otno thgiew sti fo erom dehsup ti
,degguh dna seye desolc htoB
.kcab sih ta esuoh sih htiw yawa gnippets yb reffo eht desufer eh
.etoyoc eht t'nsaw ytisortsnom taht ,gniht tahT
,dnoces a dereviuq pil s’nonreV
,detrats nonreV ”,yeH“
”,trams er’uoy dalg os m’I“
deltsur sevael wolley ehT
.ymmud fo tros emos saw siht noisulcnoc eht ot emoc ot ydaer saw nonreV
,tor dna dlom fo knuts htaerb yhtrae s’tI
,tuo gnillac erofeb dnuorg eht otno sucum pu gnikcah ,teef sih ot esor nivlA
.taorht sih ni thguac saw eciov s’nonreV
,mih fo tuo kcuf eht gnikaerf saw gnihtyreve hguohT .gnitpmet saw ti
,lla ta dneirf sih t’nsaw mih fo tnorf ni llits yltcefrep gnidnats erutaerc sihT
.tuo emac sdrow elbigilletni on tub ,yob rehto eht ot pu llac ot deirt eH
",enil thgiarts a ni gniog erew eW"
.efil sih ni nees reve d’eh gnihtyna ekilnu saw dna
.sdnah nevolc sti ni gnihton dehgiew eh fi sa gnikool
.ydob ysmilf sti rof hcum oot tnemevom yna
,htaenrednu demriuqs dna demaercs htoB
sehcrib eht fo krab etihw dna sevael wolley eht neewteB
etihw eht daetsni saw
.evren lacitpo na morf ylgnignad
,devom reven htuom sti hguohT .eugnot nwonknu
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
,htaenrednu ruf deniur emas taht gnilaever
,htap sih dekcolb skao dna smlE
.guh thgit a yb tem yletaidemmi saw dna teef sih ot delbmarcs eH
.spans prahs dna spop ni delkcarc mih htaenrednu egailof dna sgiwt ehT
,weiv ni smug ro spil on htiW
.nonreV sdrawot drawrof seenk s'ti deggard ti
.nonreV ot yaw sti no meht revo delwarc tsuj erutaerc eht tub
,tsrif ta dnatsrednu t’ndid nonreV
.dnoces taht ta lerriuqs eht deciton tsuj ylno ti fi sa
.dnuor-og-yrrem a no gnitsiwt saw eh fi sa
.sbuc gniltserw ekil htrof dna kcab gnikcor
?revopeels a rof elttes dluow nivlA ebyam
,gniraelc a ta ylnO
daeh sih fo sedis htob ot deyalps srae ,kcohs ni kcab depmuj dah etoyoc ehT
tuo sih saw siht fI