.yteirav erom tol a
.derreferp stciP eht daow eulb eht ekilnu saw siht
,feiler ni dehgual eH ”!devas er’eW
.erom on era nem ehT“
,ffo taob eht hsup ot edam I
mih degguh aderG
# .deedni emoclew yrev tlef I
stsaoC nrehtroN eht fo sevlow riaf ew taht yas emoS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,floWisakiM yb
,erhco hsidder fo sgnikram tniap dna
.nidO ot htlaeh ruo gniknird erew ew sa grihskraR otni degrahc stciP lacol eht nehw rof-
,seert eht gninnacs seye
.rotaerC dna ediuG ruo
.sroirraw sih fo tseb eht edisgnola
,esirprus taerg ym oT
?sdneirf dna kayneK ot sneppah tahw tuo dnif ot emit txen
,rellit eht dna slias eht neewteb gnithgif
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.delf dna liat denrut I dna
uoy sselnu ,dah reve ti naht retsaf pu kcab emac sgniggel yM ”!kcatta rednu er’eW“ .denihw d’eh ”!kayneK“ .gnikamyrrem etavirp ruo fo tsdim eht ni su deppots ohw eh saw ti os dna
,deilper esiwrehto ro deggurhs sevitan eht fo lareveS
.denoitnemnu tfel tseb slliks ro ,ssennekopstuo
,taht ylper ot htuom ym denepo I
,sevlesmeht seolf eci eht fo nrob erew
.dnal no kcab su detiawa tahw deirrow erom saw I ,traeh ym nI
.nees eb dluoc depib ron laref rehtien ,llet dluoc I sa raF
.snoinapmoc fo lufwap a tub htiw saeS neveS eht gnilias ma
gninettalf srae ym
,sremocwen rieht detaert sevitan eht woh saw siht fI
em dnuora deklaw feihC ehT
era dneirf ruoy dna uoY
,sesuoh enots dna doow detcurtsnoc ylreporp ni gnipeels ot desu erew su fo llA
?dedavni gnieb sgnikiV
.etsat rof gnitnuocca on yllaer s’ereht tub ,wonk t’ndid I kiroR ni was enoyna tahw ,niagA
ev’ew taht llet dluoc I ,tserof ybraen eht ni seert eht fo ecnaraeppa dna epahs eht morF
.tnemom yna trapa emoc dluoc ti ekil dekool ten taht ,sediseB
;roirraw a mih gnillac tniop elttil saw erehT
.seert eht ni gnivom gnihtemos s’erehT“
”?egnahc teid rieht diD
.tnet s’feihC eht fo tuo emoc tsuj t’ndah eh fi sa
,tnet s’feihC eht ta draeh eb dluoc noitommoc taerg A ”.wonk I
,su dettops dna esuoherots eht dnuor emac srekcatta eht sa tsuj ffo tsac I dna kiroR
.tnetni lli tnaem snirg rieht dezilaer dna
sa hcus ,enod eb ot dedeen revetahw htiw klofegalliv eht depleh yeht erehw
”.ekil eb dluow gnitnerap tahw derednow syawla I
”?nuf eb ot tnaem saw gniod saw I tahW“ .deilper I
emussa ot esle enoyna ro ,uoy fo suoutpmuserp s’tI
,did ti sa gnipoohw tuo-nward gnol a evag osla yehT
.em dniheb wap sih gnitniop ,kiroR derettulps ”,yaw taht sllug er’ereht ,kayneK“ .reh ta srae ym dereggaw I
.suineg ,enod lleW
,erew uoy erehw rettam on ;ecnaraeppa lasrevinu rieht erew seert tuoba gniht ehT .derettum I
”.ecno ta kcab lias ot evah eW
,semalf eht fo gnilkcarc eht gnieb dnuos ylno eht
.tisiv a diap srobhgien lufthgiled ruo nehw tsol saw pihsenahT eht wenk lla ew ,sediseB
.ruf tnrub fo tnecs eht htiw degnit
.htgnerts ym pu peek t’ndluoc relaeh lacol rieht yb swerb eht nevE
,pu srae rieht dah aderG dna akleV
.ssel on ,snoinapmoc fo gnimeesnu tsom eht htiW
.klofnemow kukiuR eht deraor ”!lliw reH ecrofnE“
.su dnuora lla aes sselerutaef eht
;traeh ta srethgif erew su fo rebmun a taht timda I
,thgin erew ti fi nevE
su deffins feihC ehT
.erutuf ruoy ot yek eht seil seilleb ruoy nihtiW
.thgin tsal dennalp dah ew tahw fo yaw eht ni teg ot dednet snopaeW
.strap eseht ot neeb reven
.ycagel reh htrof yrrac ot sbuc etaerc ew llahs os ,elpoeP ehT detaerc dah ehS sa tsuJ
.sraeps dna sreltna htiw su nopu tes stciP eht ,llah eht edistuo degar mrots a elihw
.eb ti tel pihsenahT eht taht
.pihsenahT dezar-yltnecer ruo morf dednal ew raf woh gnillet oN
.skcab ruo tsniaga desserp sraeps
.thgin rehtona eviws ot devil evah t’ndluow ew
.nekops t’ndah I ekil no deirrac retaW feihC tuB
,tnemetats taht ta desirprus demees kiroR .ylderit deksa I
.elims a ni tes waj reh
,gnitsuahxe saw ecneirepxe elttil htiw taob a gnilias taht uoy llet I nehw em eveileb tub
,elttab ni naht eid ot yaw esrow raf a saw llag no-lluf a gnirud ffo gnitsac taht draeh I
,wollawS-dooG akleV saw
.retaW feihC dias ”,erahs ot swen lufrednow sah relaeH ehT“
,snoitisop gnileenk otni su decrof sevlow ehT
.enod erew ew retfa tseuqnoc tsetal ym deksa I
.aes eht fo sdaor lairomemmi eht yb
.uoy rof kiroR s’tahT
…thgin tsal esuoherots eht ni taht gniod tpek ti nehw yllaicepsE
,erohs ot meht dellup sevlow eht fo owt sa demaercs aderG dna akleV
.stnecs rehto yna pu kcip t’ndluoc I hguoht
.gnirb dluow rigÆ fo sretaw tnelubrut eht tahw gniwonk ton
.tlenk yeht erehw derevihs
)?( feihC reh sa em morf yawa deppets em gnidloh sseflow ehT
.cinut ym fo tnorf eht yb thgirpu em dellup neht
.kiroR detnemmoc
.yldetatiga gnikcilf liat reh
.deeh on aderG dna akleV diap esiwrehto dna
,dessih I ”?naem uoy od tahW“
,llew sa thgirpu kiroR dellup ehs
.gnihtyreve dna htraeh til-ylreporp a dah ti fi
.yas ot dah feihC eht tahw raeh ew retfa tsael ta rO
,dekcal ew dnal eht fo sehcir tahw niatbo ot si egallip dna reuqnoc ew nosaer eht tahT
,ekam I noitseggus yreve roF
,rolias a fo hcum reven saw I
.rehto eht ni daemdoolb fo draknat dehsinifnu na dna ,sgniggel ruoy no wap eno htiw thgiarts gnikniht yrt uoy tsuj tub
”?ew era allahlaV ni erehW“
sroirraw sih dna lraJ eht rehtaf ym ,woN .em thguac tsomla rehtaF nehw yromra eht ni enola emit eno taht detnuoc
seituaeb owt eht htiw gnola I dna kiroR evord taht slliks tabmoc roop sa raef hcum sa saw ti dna
smra reh dedlof akleV
.pihsenahT ym tsuj htiw feeb evah dluow stciP eht ylekil ton s’tI“ .deralg akleV
,dehcaeb ew emit eht yb eros erew skcab dna smra ruO
,noitirtta yraew hguorht rehtie saw tI
.ti ot meht nruter ew llahs os
.taob tseraen eht ot
”.rettaf gnitteg lla era sregalliv ehT“
.wap ni sraeps dna sexa ,seert eht fo tuo tsrub serugif fo puorg a ,tniop sih evorp oT
;stnalp ym wenk I ekil t’nsaw tI .nworb dna neerg
,etats tnerruc ruo nevig dnA
!deneppah tahw wonk ot deen elpoep yM“ .akleV dellir ”!girrekS ot teg ot tog ev’ew ,kayneK ,eye s’nidO yB“
.sregalliv tnereffid htiw srevopeels
,mrahc dna skool doog ym detsiser ehs
.xepa eht ot yawflah ydaerla nus eht saw noitcerid fo rotacidni ylno eht dna
.erif eht rof emag thguac-yltnecer gniraperp
,esirprus taerg ym oT .dehcaorppa
.shtnom owt tsrif eht gnirud erew yeht sa gnidnamed sa t’nerew klofsebirt eht tsael tA
,tenalPruF yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
,retteb wonk ot tog ew slag owt htiw yawa gniviws esuoherots a ni saw yddub ym dna em tcaf eht rof ton ti ereW
.smra ym deppalf I sa dias I
.su sdrawot gnihsad sroirraw eht tuoba gnihtemos deciton neht tub
,erif eht yb swap ym gnimraw tas I
,srehto eht fo yna naht redlo raf eb ot tog s’ehs taht tcaf eht etipseD
”!ees dna tiaw tsuJ
.stroffe ruo hguorht nellows seilleb
.kiroR ,rednow t’nod I“
,kiroR gniees nO
.nwo ruo no hguone llew thgif kukiuR eht fo nemow eht tuB“
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
,erif eht ta tas eH .kiroR deilper
,ekops emoh kcab sevitan eht egaugnal eht ekil gnihtyna dnuos t’ndid tI
!dneirf ym ,nuf eb annog s’tI“
,deworran seye s’feihC ehT ”.erutuf ruO
.gnihton terger I
!ronoh ruo no tnorffa siht thgir nac yeht ylnO
srehto fo sdnal eht edavni ew yhw
”.evol ym ,oot uoy ees ot eciN“
.etarobale erom raf erew ruf reh nopu sgnikram eht dna
.edis ot edis morf taob eht dekcor taht ecnad yrrem rieht htiw tahw ,yllarutan
noitagivan-ortsA fo egdelwonk yratnemidur ym
”,sworc eht rof doof eb ydaerla yam elpoep ruoy ,gniog s’kcul ruo yaw eht htiw ,sediseB“
elttil tnaem ti tub ,saw tsaE eht erehw wonk ot doog yrev lla s’tI
.nuf rof saw gniod erew ew tahw did enoyna yhw nosaer niam eht ,sey
.tuo tfel tlef d’ehs fi gnirednow em dah ti tub
dellacnu ylhgih saw ti os ,raeD rehtaF ton ,ti did nem sih dna rehtaf s’rehtaf ym ,sediseB
,seitivitca roirp ruo fo eugitaf eht htiw gnola ,sihT
.sselehtenon sbuc eris ot detcepxe saw roirraw yreve tub ,fo draehnu toN
.neeb t’ndah ew erehwemos fo tsaoc eht ffo erew ew fi
!gnitsuahxe s’tI ?nuF“
,floWisakiM yb ”agaS s’kayneK“
.dednetni nup oN .tnemom eht fo taeh eht ni deciton t’ndah I taht nwo reh fo sracs raw lareves dah ehS
,su gnidloh seno eht ot revo ecnalg a ksir tub pleh t’ndluoc I
,semit ytfif tsal eht sa doog hcum sa od dluow gninialpxe taht dezilaer I nehT
,ekil uoy fi secnereffid larutluc ot pu ti klahc dluoc uoY
!lla retfa pihsenahT eht morf raf os t’nera ew ebyaM“
,tser eht naht rehgih desiar saw liat reH
”.enola er’ew kniht t’nod I“
,I yhw nialpxe ot em wolla tub
.htroN eht fo rorreT eht
lwocs a kcab tib I
,ega ym tuoba naht erom on eb ot smialc wolliW-gnixelF
.tsaoc eht otno ylregnig tuo deppets I dna
gnizilaer rieht erofeb yats dluoc ew gnol os ylno saw ereht ,dias tahT
.dnik ni etacorpicer ot neht yb derit oot saw I tub ,derettalf saw I
”agaS s’kayneK“yojne esaelP
raH .lworg uoy raeh I !hgual a tahW
.sevlow erew eseht
.noitanalpxe desufer ronoh dna edirp sseldne ruo taht saw
,ygolohtna xoF eht tahW
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a
,egalliv ruo fo rovivrus rehto ylno eht saw wolS eht aderG
.em erofeb sthgis lufrednow eht ni gnikat seye ym htiw ,gninialpmoc saw I taht toN
,meht fo erac doog ekat ot tfel s’taht lla erew kiroR dna I fI
.tiw-wols s’pihsenahT eht
,eno sa dna ,elpoep reh ot sdnammoc lareves dekrab ehS
.rehtegot gnikcolf rehtaef a fo sdrib fo elpmaxe rehtona tey ,dettiw-wols ylralimis saw ehs
.sgnik rieht gnillik dna segalliv rieht gnigallip ,devirra tsrif ew nehw stseug fo tseb eht t’nerew ew ,eruS
.edisni kcab teg ot etsah ym ni taob eht dezispac tsomla I ,esra s’rirneF
# .od ll’ew tahw s’taht neht
.llaf ti ees ot yppah
,tnet reh ot htuom eht ta doots retaW gnihsuG feihC
,klofsnalc reh fo tser eht ot dekool ehS .kcen ym tsniaga
.fo hguone teg ot mees t’nac egalliv enif siht ni elpoep eht gnihtemos
”.buc htiw won era klofnemow lla taht demrifnoc sah relaeH ehT
.stniop gnorts ym t’nerew gnirehtag rebmul dna gnigarof
,ecnelis elbanoinapmoc ni tas eW
.yb og ot gnihtyna erew stsehc gnilppir erab rieht fi ,sevlow dehsabanu ,eninimef yreV
.retal skeew fo elpuoc a reh ot pu ti gnikam deirt I os
.yad yreve rehto hcae ees ydaerla t’ndid yeht fi sa
,tuo tog ehs nehT
.nrut reh tiaw ot evah ot gniog s’ehs os ,noitca eht no ni reh tel ot
!sreksihw s’ikoL
desolc sretsis fo puorg a ot gnignoleb tnet a fo palf eht retfa ylno saw tI
?etuc taht dnuof I yas reve I diD
su dellac neve emoS
,nevorpnU eht kayneK
,maerts a dnuora deltsen stuh niks fo detsisnoc hcihw ,egalliv eht ot tog ew nehW
,pihsenahT eht ta kcab semit neetfif tsrif eht retfa taht od ot ton mih gninraw pu evag I
,ekops ehs sa elims a deirrac ehS
.tnelis tpek I os
edalb reh fo egde eht tlef I litnu thgir ,stillacamahctahw reh ta kool doog a tog I
”.emoh raen erehwyna er’ew kniht t’nod I dnA
,yawa del esiwekil gnieb osla erew aderG dna akleV taht was dna kcab dekool I
.ffuh a htiw yawa gninrut erofeb em ta seye reh deworran akleV
htolcniol reh morF
,timda ot saw ti gnissarrabme sa dnA
wenk ylurt eno on yhw nosaer enO
,euh ynwat a fo ruf htiW .llew
.srehtaf eb ot gniog era I dna uoy taht sraeppa tI“
.hguone llew boj sti did ti tbuod on dah I ,enots fo saw ti hguoht dna
.suoregnad evorp dluoc eno rehtie
.eson eht no em deppin dna
htnom driht eht yB
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
,yawa klofnem ruo koot retaW taerG ehT sa tsuJ“
,nihtiw secalperif yna dah stuh eht fo enoN
.sdnal wen nopu mialc ruo ekats ot tsrif eht dna
.su tsniaga smra pu ekat ot dediced srobhgien doog ruo taht pils tel naht
.gnirevauq eciov sih ,kiroR dias ”?kayneK“
sa meht ekil gnihton dekool yeht ,neht tub
.eugnot rieht fo ecnalbmes emos denrael ew ,emit revO
detrats neeb dah tahw no yrrac ot elpoeP eht sa ytud ruo si ti roF
,rigÆ fo ycrem eht ta taob ruo tes taht
,erutseg lufyalp a neeb evah dluoc tahw ni sgnaf reh derab ehS ”.won nem ruo
.thgiarts seitiroirp ym teg t’ndid I fi em esucxe ll’uoy os ,knird ot daemdoolb girrehS fo tseb eht dah ew taht netfo t’nsaw tI
,tsahga ni siht ta derats akleV
.ria nepo eht ni ssorca gniyrrac eciov reh
,kcattaretnuoc a rof epahs yna ni t’nerew
.seiradnuob larutluc
,tnet s’relaeh eht sdrawot gniklaw seituaeb eht fo lareves deips I .deilper I
tsuj esilaer ot ylno ,dnabtsiaw ym rof dehcaer I
.ecnetsixe fo dnik yna rof hsrah oot hcum erew
.ekops I ”!feihC ,ecivres fo eb ot deronoH“
.dnas eht ni tsrif-elzzum dednal yeht sa
neewteb ni yllanoisacco meht was I
.sddo esoht hgiew ot niatfeihc ro dlaks eb ot evah t’ndid uoY
.sdneirf doog hcus erew ew yhw snosaer eht fo eno saw erutan gniogysae sih dna ,nosaer emos rof mih ekil ot demees selamef rehto eht tuB
.su naht meht fo erom ynam os erew ereht
.ffo hsup ot dedeen ew esac ni tuo waptoof eno
.demranu ylsuoires erew ew neht
.erutats reh rof ytirohtua dna
.girrekS morf enaht gniknar-hgih a fo rethguad
.feiler cimoc fo dnik a sa sagas esoht tuo derugif syawla
.saw dworc eht erehw ot kiroR gnikoms a deggard I
htmraw elbanosaer evag hcihw
htrib ruo fo sdnal eht
.htrof degrus yeht
”.tsael ta ,ytrap rehto eht rof ,lleW
.noitcerid thgir eht ni rellit dna slias eht gnirevuenam tuoba tes I dna kiroR sa
# .mrots eht fo ycrem eht ta su gnivael
.llaw dleihs ruo ni nemow yna evah t’ndid pihsenahT ym ,wenk I sa raf sA
eno siht ,srae dna kcen eht dnuora ruf delzzirg htiw
.tsap eht ni lla saw taht tuB
.aderG fo mosob elpma dna smra ediw eht otni flesmih gniworht
.ni emac enil ni txen eht dna
.snoitidnoc gnivil ruo tuoba sgnivigsim ym dah tsrif I
”.did ’sruO .kiroR ,oN“
”,nruter t’ndid dna ,elpoep ruo fo ymene eht thgif ot tnew yehT
.rae ym otni deffuns wolliW
.ecnetepmoc ym fo derhs a evah t’ndluow kiroR dna
,ees dluoc eye eht sa raf sa ,dnuora dnal elbisiv on saw erehT
,efink a werd ehs
”?eiteews ,taht od ew esoporp uoy od woh dnA“
”agaS s’kayneK“ fo strap 2# fo 1# eht eht saw sihT
,elpoep ruo ot tnorffa eht thgir ot retaW taerG ehT ssorca dellevart klofnem ruo ecnis revE“
,did eh revetahw no detartnecnoc ylluf reven eh kiroR dlot syawla dah I
,enO yaD no stnet rieht otni em deggard srotius ym ecnis reve yvne htiw neerg neeb dah
dednecsnart taht egaugnal a flesti saw taht
a reh evig saw od dluoc I lla dna
.def-llew I dna kiroR tpek yeht ,tcaf ni
.spil reh gnikcil
.ynam fo srehtaf ,rehtar rO
.egami reH ni nem owt fo gnisselb a su evig ti did os
”?kiroR ,nuf gnivaH“
aderG dna akleV ,kiroR
.su rof erots ni yal tahw ezilaer em dah skcab dna smra s’kiroR dna
.drawrof deppets sevlow eht fo enO
,kiroR ekil tsuJ
;tnegilgen morf raf erew sregalliv ehT
tfel ygrene ro emit hcum em evag kukiuR eht ekil t’nsaw ti tuB
.tnemelttes ruo ni slraK raeb wef eht fo eno erew dna
”,syaw ruo netaerht secneulfni lanretxe tsel ,tnednepedni eb ot evah ew ,elpoeP a sa tuB“
.noisserpxe ”?tcepxe uoy did tahW“
.saes eht fo nnutöJ ythgimla
,regnol on su desserppo klofnem ruo nehw modeerf eurt dnuof dah ew sa tsuJ“
.sdnal rieht morf detuor eb reven dluow
.gnihtolc ro romra fo mrof emos nod ot dednet yeht neve tuB
.elims ygnaf ,dezad a htiw don dluow eh
,god.ecioveht ta
”.traehteews ,stcaf eht gnitats tsuJ
.kiroR derednow
,ronaemed mlac a rehtie ekopseb eman esohw flow-ehs A
,snoitidnoc larutlucirga roop ot eud evael ot gnivah fo kaeps ot
,aes eht hguorht seirassime reh tnes dah llA shtriB ohW ehS sa tsuJ“
,su fo eno yreve dna hcae ta kool gnol a koot ehS
.ereht ydaerla erew aderG dna akleV
.tnet eht fo roolf eht ot em delkcat yllacitcarp yeht sa nettogrof noos erew taht fo sthguoht llA
.hsilkcit teg ot detrats ti nehw elggig ot ton od dluoc I lla saw ti dna ,yaw rehto yreve dna hcae
,nruter ot deliaf os gniod ni dna
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup
,dlrow ruo fo saes tsav eht ot tuo tes tsrif dah eW
.yaw taht retteb hcum sleef tI .kiroR ,eyA“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
dah I tub ,smra pu koot ohw selamef
.dednuorrus su dah ylkciuq srekcatta eht dna ,ffo gnihsup ym ni yaled eht ot detubirtnoc siht ,saw melborP
.ton ro ti ekil ,erew lla ew
.reh ta eye rebma deddil-flah a tsac I
ecarg niatrec a deirrac
.tuo gniffulf liat ot kcen ym morf nwod yaw eht lla ruf eht tnes hcihw
,hguorht thgin eht peels ot lla su del
.pu emac kiroR ,neht tsuj dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
daem dedoolb fo tseb eht yb deldda
.fo serohs eht nopu tfird ew sdnal
,sevlow rehto eht htiw deriap mih gnitteg fo ytilibissopmi eht ro
.pu derots doof fo tol a dah ydaerla yeht derugif I tub ,seitud rehto rieht fo yna ro ,gnitnuh did klofegalliv eht fo rewef dna rewef ,yletaL
,llA shtriB ohW ehS yB
”?su ot neppah ot gniog tahw ,kayneK“
,nwo ruo llac ot sdnal wen rof hcraes ni ylerem saes eht lias ew yas srehto teY
egayov tsrif sih no tuo gnittes nos sih denigami evah reven dluoc eh tuB
.ecnailer fo tniop eht ot su eit dluow taht sdnob eht ffo tsac ot evah ew
,dekool ti naht ksat tluciffid erom A
sroirraw fo tsecreif eht taht
.redlo raf dellems ehs hguoht
.srotcetorp wap raew ot thgiserof eht skcal eh ,yadot lliT
.hguone noos tnet ytpme na dnif dluoc ew erus m’I
.gnikaerbkcab noitnem ot ton
,erew elpoep ym sa ydrah sa roF
.I dna kiroR rof elbayojne yllanoitpecxe saw htnom tsrif ehT
.ecnalg dnoces a naht erom meht droffa t’ndid srotpac rieht hguoht
.ezingocer t’ndid I egaugnal a fo selballys fo gnirts a derettum dna
,pleh hcum fo t’nerew slrig ehT
.stnet nwo rieht otni kiroR dna em teg ot gnithgif yllacitcarp erew sevlow eht
,elihw gnol a ekil tlef tahw retfA
,emoh kcab elpoep evitan eht ekilnU
,swap rieht ni deraeppa sevink dna sexA
emit tsal eht saw tahT
”,ylsuorogiv erom hcum gnivom em no tsisni elpoep ynam oS
,deredliweB eht kiroR ,pu tsriF
,yas ot dah feihc gninnirg rieht tahw draeh sregalliv rehto eht dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dehsad erew eraD ohW esohT fo sdnal detrahcnu eht otni gnilias fo ysatnaf ym ekil skooL .llew hO
2# fo 1# traP ,floWisakiM yb
gniod nwo ruo sa elag eht fo ecrof eht sa hcumsani saw ti dna
.deracs naht suoiruc erom dekool ohw ,dneirf ym dna
gniripsni-ewa dna gnisaelp erom raf osla saw ti ,eton taht nO
,ereh shtnom eerht ruo nI
.retaW feihC dias
.aes fo esnapxe nepo eht ta gnirutseg ,deksa I
akleV .reh ot dias I
.semalf eht ot resolc ffur thgir sih delgna eh os ,degnis yltneiciffus saw ffur tfel s’kiroR ”.morf emoc sbuc erehw derednow syawla I“
.sutepmi evig ot srekcatta ruo fo seirc raw eht noitnem ot toN
.niag ruo noitcurtsed s’tnemelttes hcae htiw
.srae sih mraw ot raen daeh sih gnignirb
.ti timda t’ndid kiroR hguoht ,detsuahxe saw I
.neht dna won yreve daem dna doof dedeen srolias fo gniogtuo tsom eht neve tub ,draob no seituaeb owt dah ew ,detnarG
fo thgis eht ot ekowa ew nehw cincip on saw tI
.dah eb ot htmraw fo egatrohs on eb dluow ereht taht tnerappa noos saw ti tub
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.t’nsaw siht ,pihsgnol A
.stibah gniydnu ot ynomitset sffur sih fo ruf derrahc eht htiw
,pihsgnol a ni toN
girrekS fo pihsenahT eht morf stseug ruo ot stsoh doog gnieb erew ew elihW
srehto stsixe ereht ,noitazilivic lufrewop yreve rof ,lla retfA
.edistuo derehtag gnivah dworc a htiw
.waptoof nwo sih hguorht ecils ot ylno ,gniws drows elpmis a retsam ot woh gninrael yad eritne eht dneps dluoc eH
?reppus rof stlep rieht tnaw sevitan eht oD
,pu doots feihC eht
.saw I revetahw fo etisoppo eht yltsom gniod dneirf tseb ym htiw
.sseug s’enoyna saw kiroR ni was yeht tahw tub ,lla dna skool doog ym htiw tahw ;taht tcepxe t’ndid I yas t’ndluoc I
,snoitidepxe tnerruc ruo fo hcaer eht dnoyeb raf levart llahs I ,yademos taht deerced dah rehtaF
”?dnuora nem rehto on yeht era yhw ,wolliW“
.llordeb reh ot em detivni ehs dah ecno ton
,noihsaf gnikiV eurt ni deffuh dna
.ffiks gnihsif a ni
.lla retfa ,serovinrac lla er’eW
.egaenil ruo eunitnoc ot woh no ammelid a htiw teseb neeb dah ew
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,tenhsif gnittor eht ediseb ,tfel sih nO
,pmac eht fo trap rehtona ot detageled saw aderG dna akleV
# .delworg dna ffur ym hguorht sregnif reh werd selamef eht fo enO .kcab dekrab I
,yawyna ,llew taht hsif t’ndluoc I
;srevopeels gnirud deriuqer saw ti taht toN
.no sevil ycagel ruo ,meht hguorhT
,selims lla erew yeht dezilaer I nehw flesym dnefed ot tuoba saw I
,od ot retteb gnihtyna gnivah toN
;emas eht hcum dekool yeht
.raf os sevitan elam yna nees t’nevah ew yhw derednow I taht
deirrac eb ot denitsed hcus sa dna
.kcab yaw ruo gnidnif ni pleh t’ndluow
.devirra tsrif ew nehw mils os demees dah yehT“
.sknaht on tub ,sknahT .rah-rah-
”!lliw reH ecrofnE
ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.dehcuorc yeht erehw gnireviuq
.yadretsey sa hcus sthgin no noinapmoc derreferp s’kiroR osla saw ehS
.knird ot daem yna dah I
,”snediamdleihs“ fo ekops taht sagas erew erehT
# .sredavni sti ot llef egalliv nwo ruo sa tsuj dereflip ew ffiks gnihsif a tub
.htrof deppets meht fo eno dna
fo strap 2 fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
?but siht no sevil ruo fo tser eht dneps ot tnaw yllaer ew od tuB
.smra eht yb su del yeht sa gniggawa sliat
.ylleb reh fo eglub eht nopu gnitser swap
.tuo tfard eht peek ot hguone doog llits erew ruf dna sehtolc ruo os ,saw emoh dlo ym naht redloc hcum t’nsaw tI
,devirra ew sa noos sA
.reve sa sseleulc ,kiroR deksa
,tnereffid yaw tlems ria eht ,sediseB
eht ni deraeppa ylremrof evah ”agaS s’kayneK“
em nwod swap rieht nar srotpac ym fo lareves yaw ehT
.gnihcraes syawla
egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no
,draob ot tsrif eht eb ot saw I
;gnirednaw syawla ,yaw nwo ruo ni sdamoN