”.eiteews ,oot uoy evol I“
.dootsrednu I egaugnal evitan ylno eht ot dehctiws I os
.retto elamef eht morf elims a dna don A
.detnemmoc akleV
.sregalliv gniogtuo fo elpuoc a dna em fo pleh eht rof ton ti erew
.neht ecnis deneppah dah hcum os tuB
,I taht saw rettam eht fo tcaf eht tub
.sgnaf dna swap erab ym naht erom elttil htiw yerp laref tnuh ot ytiliba ym detbuod I ,wohemoS
.lla ti nees ev’I“
.stug hsif fo llems eht dnats reven dluoc ehS
.drow elgnis a sa detnuoc ylekil taht tub ,naom tuo-nward a detnuoc uoy sselnu toN
teg ot em rof hguone gnol
,sroloc larutan ni detniap neeb dah yehT
,skcab rieht nopu gnihtabnus yal sretto elamef lareves
.sa su wonk dluow srehto srethgif deraef eht emaceb retal dna
,rehtom dna efiw doog a osla saw tub
,devirra d’ew ecnis sraey eht nI
.erauqs egalliv eht hguorht su del sehsiF-owT sa neve neppah t’ndid taht tub
.dnuorg eht nopu ylffits gniyl
wonk dluow I tahw fo thgil eht yb tas sretto owT
,enahT a fo rethguad a neeb dah akleV
,eniw ro daem fo lufylleb a retfa detnuocer yllausu saw ti taht neviG
.yrd deklim gnitteg revo elbatrofmoc-naht-ssel
.pu gnikool yllanif erew sgniht taht deraeppa tI
?aes eht otni kcab su nworht evah dluow yeht
.su htiw taob ruoy wot ll’eW“
,akleV ot egairram yM
dediced srotsecna ym taht noitseuq tuohtiw suht saw tI
.hcniw a htiw yawa meht ekat ot em rof hguone drah meht dekcams dna
.tsaf ylbakramer nar yeht ,buc htiw erew ohw elpoep roF
dias si tI“  .dehsinif t’ndah
eht ni deraeppa ylremrof evah ”agaS s’kayneK“
”.ecneuqesnoc on fo era scifironoh ruO
.ni tuc ,yarra yeltom ruo rof flowsekops eht ,I tub
.elat eht no yrrac ot devivrus eh ylno dna
.snevaeh eht ot daeh sih denrut kiroR
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a
,yretsym ni deduorhs saw ecalp eht gnivael elpoep ym fo sliated eht tuB
.sklawdraob eht gniniatniam ro ,gnihsif ,gnidliub ti eb
.ria eht dednuoser slley dna smaercs
”.noitcerid taht ni og ot evah tsuj ew os ,yad hcae tes nus eht erehw fo eton nekat ev’I“
.hcae sevitan ruof gniyrrac ,sruo ot tnecajda staob owt erew ereht dezilaer I neht saw ti dna
.hguorht dna hguorht sroirraw erew yeht
sgnikiV evarb su fo ruof ehT
?roirraw deb a tub gnihton er’uoy taht timdA“
ylimaf dna efiw ym taht ecalp A
.swap sih ffo gnildnah neeb dah eh revetahw fo stnanmer eht ffo gnihsurb ,evac eht tuoba decap iellaW feihC ”,em lleT“
.rotcurtsni na sa devlovni tog kiroR taht detsisni yeht
t’nod I“ .delf d’ew dnal eht sdrawot tuons reh dekrej ehS
,tuo dekcehc stessa s’kiroR dna em evah ot detcepxe-flah I
,erus rof saw taht ,srethgif delliks erew yehT
.efil wen a trats ot ecnahc ruo eb dluoc siht dezilaer neht
”.ti ot sthgir gnihsif elos eht sdloh ebirt ruo yas dluow sretto redlo eht tub
,sdradnats retto yb ,suonrevac saw evac ehT
.taht yas t’ndluow I“
,guh a ni smra sih denepo retto ehT
,elbayojne rehtar neeb lla dah tI
llah daem eht ni sreknird yretsym a
,htrae dehsurc dna doolb fo sgnikram tniap dah owt eseht
,revewoh ,enots eht fo ecafrus eht no skramlesihc yna ees t’ndluoc I
,tseb thguoht I tahw od ot gniyrt ylno saw I
,sretto owt yna naht regnorts hcae
,su ot denrut feihC ehT
”.yaw taht syats ti
.egde ecreif a no gnikat detrats enot rieht
.em ediseb dnats ot pu gnimoc ,akleV dias ”.dnabsuh ,yad dooG“
.gninoitseuq ni deweks sreksihw s’iellaW
.lias eht fo cirbaf eht hguorht neve pu dekcip slirtson ym taht tnecs egnarts a tub
,yademos taht su dlot yeht dna
yas ot em fo ssimer eb dluow ti dna
”!dnatsrednu I esruoc fO
,enecs txen eht ot denrut I
,tuo su dekcik yltnecer os dah taht eno eht saw ebirt ymene eht fi eriuqni ot tuoba dekool kiroR
.ssol taerg tuohtiw ton tub
,s’kiroR fo taht spahrep dna
”,saw taht dnal nekasrof-sdoG revetahw no devirra ew nehw dnA“ ”—tub ,oN“
…tibah a eb ot gnitteg si sihT
.thgin rehtona desoporp tseb eb dluow ti em dlot woleb nwod baj kciuq a dna lworg a tub—dnatsrednu uoy ,yrros saw I reh wohs ot—
.desufnoc elttil a teg ot gnitrats ,deksa I
,drow retteb a fo kcal rof ,saw tI
.gniliec eht hcaer ot retto hcae fo pot no dnats ot dedeen sevlow owt gninaem
.eniw ekam ot woh sretto eht dewohs I ecnis reve
.mih tuoba lla gnicnarp dna gnipael
fo erom gnikniht m’I
.woleb nwod sdnal detrahcnu fo royevrup ,nevorpnU eht kayneK sa nwonk neeb dah I
”.oot snoinapmoc ym dnA“ .dias I
,egalliv ’sretnuhelahW eht ot txen hcaeb eht no
.erew kiroR sgniht wef erew ereht
ni sevlesmeht dessorgne won yb dah ohw
,dias ecno roirraw suomaf a sA
.oga emit gnol a tiuq evah dluow eh
.em rof hguone doog t’nsaw ehs fi derednuht dah ehs
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,gnol oot gnirats neeb evah tsum I
.gniwohs sgnaf rieht
# ”?trats ew od nehW“
,tsaoc eht no dednal ew nehW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dah I dna aderG ekil serohc rieht htiw tuo gnipleh
.ynam htiw deb otni dna
,evael ot etsah ruo nI
iellaW feihC tub ,dias I
”.elpoep ruo ot taerht siht retnuoc ot elba neeb evah dluow yeht
retto eht dias ”,ssucsid ot hcum si erehT .feihc ruo ot su
,sdrawkcab gnurps I sa lley a evag I
,I dna akleV rof sA
,taob ruo fo lluh eht revo gnireep secaf lareves erew em erofeB
.ylsuoires selat eht koot yllautca eno on
,sevitom roiretlu evah thgim eh ,eruS“
.erehwyna gnat taht ezingocer dluow I neht tub
,tenalPruF yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH
,elbaccepmi saw esroN siH
,dootsrednu su fo enon egaugnal a ni kcab gnirebbaJ
.terces a ecnetepmocni sih peek ot evah ot gniog tsuj er’eW …kiroR rof sA
.evac eht otni repeed su del dna
.klawdraob eht no pag a otni deklaw I erofeb thgir mra ym fo dloh thguac
.gnillet fo tibah siht dah elpoep ym sagas sseltnuoc eht fo eno derebmemer I .esruoc fO
.elzzun a reh evag I ”.efas dna
”?semoh ruoy morf nevird neeb ev’uoy taht dnatsrednu I .nemesroN ,oS“
,tnemelttes kukiuR eht ekilnU
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,taob eht fo retnec eht ni rehtegot deldduh
.roines ym sraey ytnewt neeb evah thgim ohw enoemos htiw saw ti fi neve
,stneduts retto ym fo eno htiw deb ni em thguac akleV retfA
.lla su devas snoitca sih timda ot evah ew tub
.kayneK ,sdnal ruo morf raf er’eW“  .dessorc smra
gnikiV rehto yreve ekil
.gnimoclew naht erom neeb dah sretto eht
thgin ta taob a no peelsa gnillaF
.yrotcafsitas naht erom saw ecnamrofrep ym taht tnaem
.esroN kaeps dluoc sevitan eht erehw rgnavklóF ro allahlaV emos otni tfird ot ylno
.stra gnithgif eht ni sretnuhelahW eht niart ot noitativni ruO
.gniyenruoj ruo fo dne eht eb dluow depoh ylerecnis I hcihw ssam dnal eht sdrawot taob eht revuenam ot gniyrt gnitsuahxe saw ti ,yas ot sseldeeN
.eno naht syaw erom ni ,reh ot dnik neeb dah sraey ehT
.ecnelis ni kced eht no tas
,retal dna renoos dna
,htiw taob a no flesym dnif dluow I sevlow eht lla fO
.em nopu syar reh tsac nus eht fo dog
elliamniahc fo nrettap elbakatsimnu eht gniraew ,serugif lareveS
.raf taht nettog evah ton thgim ew ,trats daeh a su gnivig fo ysetruoc s’kukiuR eht rof t’nsaw ti fI
,ti tfel d’ew erehw tsuj saw taob ehT
”?dnalniV dellac ecalp a fo draeh uoy evaH“
.edivorp ot elba eb dluow sretto eht hcihw fo owt tsrif eht
,elamef a ,elbat eht ta retto rehto eht tub
,nus gninrom eht ot ton ekowa I
”.ssetfeihC dna feihC ,esruoc fo tuB“
,dettimrep emit revenehW
.enihw a kcab tib dna
,yessydo siht no tuo detrats tsrif I nehW
esu taerg fo eb dluow ti
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,dnal ruo fo tsaoc eht ffo gnilias elpoep ruoy dnuof ew ,oga sremmus ytnewt tuobA“
.kcab deralg akleV ”.ti timdA
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup ,ygolohtna xoF eht tahW
”.evah syawla I sA“
.yltnegru irttaM ssetfeihC deksa
”!elpoep ruoy fo yhtrow sroirraw htiw sdnal eseht etalupoper ot redro ni
,drawrof deppets I sa taorht ym ni pu tliub lworg A
.ekops ohw aderG saw ti niaga tub ,yllufitip denihw kiroR elihw ,deltsirb I
.pid a ekat ot dediced yeht revenehw meht ylppaer ot dah yeht netfo woh derednow I dna
.trap eht yalp ot tseb ym did I dna ,smelborp klofnem rieht eveila ot tnes neeb d’ew thguoht elpoep esehT
snoinapmoc ’sehsiF-owT fo eno esuaceb
,spihsenahT eht nI
,deltrats dekool sremocwen ehT
.worromot stoor ro seirreb emos dnif dluoc ew taht epoh tpecxe od dluoc ew elttil saw ereht os
”?desirprus ton I ma yhW“
.em derongi ehs tub ,akleV ta ecnalg a evag I
”agaS s’kayneK“:yojne esaelP
,nosrep ruo no sehtolc eht naht erom elttil gnirb ot elbanu erew ew
.sllirf esoht fo enon dah feihC siht tuB
.ni dnal siht ot emoc dah ew but eht no kcab sevlesruo dnuof eW
,kaeps ot edam kiroR dna akleV
.nrut ni su decarbme dna
.sreksihw sih fo hctiwt a htiw
.etats ekilecnart a gniretne
”,wonk ot doog s’tahT“
deveihca ylisae eb dluoc taht gnihtemoS
.regnol on su detius emoh ruo fo snoitidnoc eht esuaceb tfel eW
epoh I .dooG“ ”.kayneK ,yad ynnus a ekil skooL“
,gniteerg emas eht aderG dna akleV dedrocca dna pu emac
,rehtaf rieht ekil tsuJ
.elihw a ni ecno drows sih htaehs ot dedeen
]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[     egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no
.snoinapmoc ym gnikaw
# .deneppah ti emit dnoces eht ylno saw siht taht nevig ,yllaer ,egnartS
.aera na ni delttes elpoep ruoy nehT“
.wob elttil a evag I .aderG dna kiroR dias ”.kayneK ,uoy knahT“ ”.daetsni em gniknaht eb lla dluohs uoy ,gnihtyna fI
”,su nettog evah dluow stciP eht
,meht dettap eh sa elims-flah a evag kiroR
,pu htgnerts ruo peek ot scinot labreh fo stnuoma suoipoc kiroR dna em def relaeh eht dna
.aderG ekops ”,kiroR did sA
.ereh nekops s’ti yltneulf woh rednow em edam hcihw
detsaor dna denniks su dah t’ndah yeht tcaf ehT
.kiroR demrifnoc ”.kcab gniog dnim
# ”.od ot retteb gnihton tog ev’ew sseuG“
,lóS sa gnisaerc seye ym
”.irttaM ssetfeihC
?deifsitas raf suht neeb sniol gnihca ruoy evaH
.kool a ekat ot thgie su tnes feihc ruo dna sruoy fo taob siht dettops nemrehsif ruO
,aes eht fo syaw eht tnrael htron eht fo sevlow ew taht sretto morf saw ti taht dias saw tI
,meht tuoba suoiruc erew eW
”.taht no em nethgilne ot evah yam uoY“
efiw ym si siht dna ,ebirT retnuhelahW eht fo iellaW feihC m’I“
.nwo ym fo eno ,kayaK deksa
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.tuh sih ot kcab gnidaeh ,deddon kiroR
!eb kiroR elcnU evaeL !sbuC“
,tnemegduj fo kcal tnerehni sih rof ton ti erew dna
?gniod uoy fo tol elohw eht era tahw oS“
.esruoc ffo nwolb neeb gnivah retfa
.thgin dloc siht no teknalb ruo lias denetsafnu eht
,nar ew nehw tips a ffo taem fo hcnuah a gnippir kiroR etipseD
.ezorf su fo ruof ehT
selam eht edisgnola thguof selamef ruo nehw ylno saw ti dna
.nekops reve dah aderG ecnetnes tsegnol eht eb ot dah tahT !skaeps ehs dnA
.ylgnidrocca dedrawer eb ot dah stneduts doog taht saw dnatsrednu t’ndid ehs tahW
?wolS eht aderG dellac eb ehs dluow esle yhW
sdleihs etik dna
,erew sdnah ym erehw ezilaer ot demees akleV
”,enO nevorpnU O ,nalp taerG“
etelpmoc neeb evah reven dluow esuoh sih taht
”?sbuc evah ot gniog aderG si nehW
,llew sa ybraen devil aderG dna kiroR
,gnorw em teg t’noD
sretto eht fo regral eht ot pu deppets sehsiF-owT
”.eno siht ot no gnah retteb uoY
gnimit dab suounitnoc ro kaerts gnireenimodrevo na rehtie tub
,retaw eht revo thgir tliub erew sretto fo egalliv eht
,evil elpoep rehto erehw og ot deen eW“
.level tsehc ot pu emac ylerab daeh sih
# ”!seman ynnuf hcus evah elpoep uoY .os yas uoy fI“
.emirc a saw did srehto woh gnivaheb fi sa tsomla
,elims gniwonk a evag iellaW feihC
.ebirt ym fo retnuh daeh ,sehsiF-owT m’I
.der dna nworb ,etihw sa hcus
.egalliv eht dekoolrevo taht ffilc a no rehtegot tliub ew esuoh a ni nwod delttes ew dna
,emit no thgir dna
,delf nemesroN eht retfa yltrohS
strap 2 fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
;yoj ni tuoba gnicnarp ekil leef uoy edam taht sretto tuoba gnihtemos saw erehT
htiw emoC“ .sraeps rieht rewol snoinapmoc sih dah ,wap sih fo evaw a htiw dna ,denethgirb retto ehT .deneppah ti taht eciwt saw ti noitnem ot gnitcelgen ,dias I
.em ot gninrut erofeb dnoces rehtona rof reh ta dekool remocwen ehT ”,thgiiiiR“
,raef ni pu nworht erew smra riehT
.syaw rieht fo tnrael noos dna ,edart deunitnoc ew ,erehT
.t’nerew ew dna demra erew yeht nehw ton
.elyts citsitra eht no tnemmoc t’ndid I hguoht
.trap ruo no tnemegduj roop saw tI .deen on s’erehT“
.seof rieht tug ot sreltna rieht esu yeht yaw eht htiw ton
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?ereh doog yna gnihsif eht sI ?skcirt s’woH“
,srehto eht ekilnU
”.ereh gnoleb t’ndid elpoep ruoy
,mih ta ylprahs dekool akleV
,sremocwen eht was dna dnuora dekool oot yeht nehW
,aderG tub yaw ym rab dluohs ohw dna
,denihw dna delworg sbuc ehT .akleV dekrab
.gniyrt fo kcal a saw ereht taht toN
.em htiw evah rehtar dluow I wef erew ereht
.taob evitan fo epyt a retfa mih deman dah I derevocsid I taht retal raey a ylno saw ti dna
.teg dluoc I tahw koot I
”?neht sliat ruoy devas I yned uoy oD
,tog I liat revetahw htiw deifsitas suht saw I
.tenhsif nettor htiw etelpmoc
spihsgnol lareves neeb evah dluoc tahw ,ti nI
.sdnal eseht ot emoc lliw
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
.nway dim ni thgir deppots I
,aes eht si siht ,detnarG
.gnileef railimaf tsomla na no nekat dah
,lla retfa aes ta tuo deid dah su fo ruof eht ebyaM
.tey tsuj gninialpmoc eb ot demees ehs taht ton
.koot iellaW hcihw
.gnidart detrats ew taht retal emit emos saw ti dna
,kukiuR eht etalupoper ot stroffe ym lla rof taht wenk ehS
nwoD
”.peek ruo nrae ot evah ot gniog er’ew tuB
.ytinummoc eht ot thguorb dah I noitidart a
serugif lareves morf yawa gninnur nees eb dluoc
”,nemesroN ,su niarT“
yhtlaeh pu worg nac
.eniw ot noisulla na gnieb ”niV“ htiw
”.yppah enoyreve speek taht tnemegnarra nA
.devresed em ekil enoyna naht erom saw hcihw
”?thgirla ,worromot degnahc sgnisserd esoht teg ot rebmemer ,kiroR“
,floWisakiM yb ”agaS s’kayneK“ fo
.enecs txen eht ot no devom eh sa
”!ereh emoc ,ereh emoC ?nemesroN“
.dnalni rehtruf seno eht sa emas eht ton tub
”.feihC ,thgir eb dluoc uoY“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,kiroR dnuora dedworc sbuc ruof ym ,kcap a sa dna
.esuap a retfa deilper I ”.od ew os ,áJ“
.tey tsuj secnahc ruo gniniur mih tnaw t’ndid I tub
.redrah denworf akleV
htiw eniw ekam ot retteb eht lla—ereht dnuof yeht seirreb dna separg eht hguorhT
?emoh ruoy tuoba gnikniht uoy ereW .aes
,drawrof ylniatrecnu sraeps rieht gnitniop
,detaefed erew seimene ruo taht
,eugnot prahs a dah ehS
sevlesmeht egrembus ro ecafrus ylkciuq ot sretto rof gniknalp eht neewteb secaps htiw
nus gnittes eht fo noitcerid eht morf nem
.evitaN nekorb ni derebbalb I ”!su ekop ton uoY
,em dniheb morf emac gnikrab deticxE
.aderG dna akleV ,kiroR ,kayneK“ ”?era uoY
.sdaeh dnuor rieht decarg taht ruf trohs eht no nees eb ylerab dluoc taht srae dnuor llams htiw ,nworb krad a fo saw ruf riehT
,dnuoba sesseccus dna sdeed ym lla htiw tuB
,sevlow erew yehT“
,neht tub ,t’nsaw eh redliub A
.delims nekops dah ohw remocwen ehT ”?’skcirt
,sevlow erew yehT
,won thgir sgnikiV yrros ytterp ekil kool tsum eW
ew ssam dnal eht tsap aera na ot walc a htiw derutseg ehS
s’woH‘ ?fo kniht nac uoy tseb eht taht sI“
”.egde neek a dloh reven lliw drows desurevo nA“
,eman nwo ym ffo yltrap mih deman dah I
”?won od ew od tahw tuB .thgiR“
.buc htfif ym eb dluow tahw saw ylleb reh nihtiW
,floWisakiM yb ”agaS s’kayneK“ fo
”!esle erehwemos yalp oG
.raeb eht dias ”,ereh fo tsew eht ot sebirt rehto erew ereht gninoitnem sregalliv eht fo eno draeh I“
”—su sllafeb taht live eht morf su tcetorp ,rirneF“
,ereh neeb evah nemesroN eht dluohs taht wenk neht eW
,taob ruo fo egde eht deppirg swap riehT
,rehto hcae tsniaga gnikahs detrats dah aderG dna akleV
.nem rolias eW
”?meht fo htnom rehtona deen uoy od rO
,dnalniV ecalp eht deman yeht—
”.relpmis gnihtoN“
.erif no liat sih tes eh emit tsrif eht naht esrow gnirepmihw saw kiroR dna
,rebmun rieht fo thgie wels nemesroN eht taht detroper elpoeP eht fo enO“
”?ereh devirra tsrif ew taht ti hguorht saw ti woh tuoba rO
,iellaW feihC dias
,nees eb dluoc buc dlo-raey-xis a yb nward
.taht fo foorp sa ylleb reh ni buc eht htiw
,gnikaeps rof eno reven saw raeb ehT
?sagas ruoy fo draeh t’nevah ew kniht uoy
,ecin yalp t’nod yehT“ .nageb I
.scinut htiw rehtob t’ndid yllausu ew os ,dnatsrednu uoy ,tneitapmi ytterp eb dluoc kukiuR ehT .sgniggel naht erom on erew
.dias yllanif ehs
.ssensseltiw lareneg reh ot ti detubirtta syawla dah I dna
,setunim wef a naht erom rof detinuer gnieb yllanif retfa aderG htiw ti ta gniog saw kiroR thguoht I ,tnemom a roF
,sbuc rieht evah kukiuR ehT
”.yrt a htrow s’tI“
,ti fo tuo yllatot saw eh fi neve no thgif ylekil dluow kiroR
”.sevlesruo yb evivrus reven ll’eW
,erew selam eht taht selor emas eht gniod erew selamef eht ,ereh taht deciton I .sklawdraob erew
,saw kukiuR eht erehw sdrawot walc a debbaj I ,ereH
.dehcaorppa kiroR
.delf yeht sa denodnaba
srehto gnivah retfa erac gnivol rednet fo deen ni selam gnuoy owt fo egatnavda ekat t’ndluow yllufepoh ohw elpoeP
.aes eht ot detcennoc syawla era sgnikiV eW“ .deddon I
,hsif ynam fo sliartne eht daer dah I
.sllaw eht no sgnitniap eht detanimulli thgil eht ,ereH
.nwod srehto eht lla kconk dluoc ohw
.kukiuR eht ot sroirraw erutuf ynam fo tfig yM
,ezis sih etipseD
.dias I ”,kleV ,netsiL“
.em no ffo debbur evah tsum seitilibisnes evitan ehT
.nemow eht sdael ehs dna ,nem eht dael I“
,rehtruf sremocwen eht etairufni ot demees ylno sihT
,ssarg gniltsur fo dnuos eht ta pu dekool I
.redro gnikrow ni meht peek ot srae ym nettalf ot dah I taht hcus
,sroirraw eht fo lareves htiw tuob a detelpmoc tsuj dah eH
.lrans a htiw em ot denrut akleV
”!setam ton er’eW“
serugif thgie detciped gnitniap a ,ereH
.evlos ot denilcni oot t’nerew
.aeS ro dnaL no emoh ta yllauqe erew taht elpoep a fo dlot sagas ruO !esruoc fO .srettO
.retaw hguorht seidob ehtil rieht fo sehsalps eht htiw gnixim sevaw eht fo dnuos eht
.reh ot ylkciuq denrut I
2# fo 2# traP ,floWisakiM yb
.sgel rieht neewteb delruc sliat
,tnepreS eht fo esrA eht yB ?uoy knahT“
,tahW“ .worbeye ym desiar I
!rehto hcae rof evol rieht derevocsid stnerap rieht retfa gnipole selpuoc owT“
.eciohc a yran htiw meht nopu decrof
,klof rehto eht morf trapa erutats niatrec a yrrac ot dednet sredael
”.os eb ot ton saw ti tuB
,elbuort fo tuo em nettog dah taht elims A
,srenosirp naht erom elttil erew eW
.enola enim tnaem I ,swap yb dnA
!ni yradnegel era
.mrah on uoy naem eW“
.mih ot derepsihw dna
.sevil ruo evah ew elihw
.htlaeh doog ni em tpek dah teid dna elytsefil s’evitan ehT
pmal lio til a pu dleh irttaM ssetfeihC
,kukiuR eht dna stciP eht morf epacse fo snaem ruo saw aes eht sa tsuJ
”?ti fo wonk ot teg tsrif elpoep ruoy did woh tub ,feihC ,em nodraP“
.elbitapmoc-seiceps t’nerew ew taht tcaf eht eb dluoc ti tuB
.trofmocsid reh gniveila
,esroN yna dnatsrednu t’ndluow syug esehT
egalliv lanoitnevnoc esiwrehto na ni syawhtap eb dluow tahW
.stciP eht morf thgilf ehT
;owt eseht deb ot gniyrt saw I taht toN
,mrahc dna skool doog ym rof t’nerew ti fi taht eergasid uoy oD
”.emoclew eb dluow ew ecalp a dnif dluoc ew thguoht dna
.demaeb iellaW feihC
.snoitca ym rof kramhcneb doog a yldrah saw taht yhw gninialpxe em deen t’nod uoy eveileb I tub
.scisab eht fo emos tnrael evah dluow os dna
,ria eht detaemrep taht gnirettihc a htiw ,elpoep ylevil a erew yehT
.htron eht fo seolf eci eht ekil ti nopu wolf sevil ruO
,I dna kiroR fo esac eht ni dna ,raeg dna snopaew ruo tuohtiw
.em erofeb thgis eht ni koot I sa erif eht revo sdnah ym gnibbur
,shtnom eerht naht erom elttil fo ecaps eht ni semoh owt morf detcive neeb dah eW
…retal sraey thgiE
.selpoep fo nepo tsom eht gnoma neve ladnacs a eb dluow ti
,sbuc eht ot kcab tnew akleV
”.erofeb wonk t’ndid I sgniht em dewohs feihC ehT“
.derewsna I ”.kleV ,yad dooG“
.tsehc ym fo ffup a htiw derewsna I ”,gnikiV eurt a ekil eviL
”?kayneK ,tuoba gnikniht uoy era tahW“
”.taht enod ,ereht neeB
.spih ym no swap ym tup I
elpoep ruoy raw fo syaw eht ni su niart ot tnes neeb evah uoy fo ruof ehT
.stnemrag reppu tuohtiw
.feihC eht dias ”,tem llew ,tem lleW“
su fo ruof eht ,egnar raeps nworht dna wob fo tuo llew erew ew ecnO
.ti htiw yawa teg dna liat ym pin dluoc ohw ees ot gniyrt ,em revo lla erew yeht noos dna
.elims gninniw tsom ym htiw dias I
.em tcejer yltnatsnoc ot esuac klofsebirt eht evag
”.esnet rehtar gnitteg
,reduol saw aes eht fo raor eht ,ereH
,daeh ym ffo lias eht detfil I sa nway peed a evag I
,sdleihs dna ,sexa ,sraeps ni gniniart cisab emos evah did I ,lla retfA
,su htiw doof yna evah t’ndid ew
strap 2# fo 2# eht eht saw sihT
.kced no swap lla eb ot evah ot gniog saw ti
.meht htiw ni evom su tel ll’yeht fi ees dna
akleV htiw ysoc teg ot edam I
eht ta gnizag uoy ees I ,noonretfa yrevE“ .akleV deksa
sdrows ,sraeps gnihsidnarb
.meht morf raw fo syaw eht nrael ot dehsiw su fo ynam dna
,rorroh laitini ym oT
.emiger gniniart rieht otni etaroprocni ot hguone yrotcafsitas slliks nopaew cisab ym dnuof yeht taht depleh tI
.smsirennam rehto htiw gnola ,deklaw yeht yaw eht ni ti eb
,ssenedur rof ecnelis ruo ekatsim ot sremocwen eht rof hsiw t’ndid I
”.won sraey thgie tsal eht rof gnirednow neeb dah I dna aderG
,sehsiF-owT dias ”,yaw sihT“
”.eerf won er’ew tub
”.od ot elbanu era kiroR dna uoy gnihtemoS
.suoiruc dna thgirb seye rieht
,kiroR derettulps ”!ireG dna ikerF dooG !nidO teewS ,hO“
,flesym ot akleV gnihctulc saw I dezilaer neht I
.elbitapmoc yllacigoloib ton tsuj erew sraeb dna sevlow taht kiroR ecnivnoc reven dluoc ew ,stroffe s’akleV dna em etipseD
,fo stseug neeb ylfeirb dah ew ebirt eht dna
evarg dekool iellaW feihC
,sremocwen eht fo eno deksa ”?esroN kaeps uoY“
.derevaw seye s’akleV
,semoh ruo fo tuo desahc erew eW .ereh gnihsif t’nera eW“
.sdnuorg gnihsif dna sdnal ruo ezies ot sroirraw rieht tnes ebirt rehtona
”.railimaf skool sihT“
”.uoy wohs dluoc I hcum os s’erehT“
.yllarutan demrof neeb evah ot dah evac eht os
?su kcits ot gniog erew kukiuR eht taht yned uoy od“
.esu hcum fo eb ot gniog era stessa ruoy ylekil ton s’ti tub ,kayneK ,esneffo oN“
.evac edisaes a otni del taht htap nedoow eht ssorca su gnidael
.pu gnithgil seye sih
tsew eht ot raf ecalp a ot gnillevart elpoep ym fo dlot sagas eht fo enO
.siht ta daeh ym koohs I  .kiroR deilper
.did eh sa gnirevaw raeps sih
”?su rof enod uoy evah yltcaxe tahw
”?eugnot ruoy kaeps nac ew kniht uoy od esle woH
.wap a desiar iellaW feihC tub ,nageb I ”—nialpxe nac I“
!gniniart morf detsuahxe llits s’eH
.slrig eht tsniaga deldduh oot eh sa talf srae
.daeha raf demool dnal fo pirts A
.taht detbuod I ,wohemoS
,selpuoc sa emac uoy ecnahc yb ton s’tI
.deksa I ”?egayov nediam ruo ekil tsuj ,esoprup dna noitcerid on htiw gnilias er’ew oS“
!kiroR elcnU !kiroR elcnU“  .dekool ti naht redrah hcum saw hcihw
.rof dlrow eht ssorca gnillevart htrow thgis a
;thgis suoirolg siht nopu ezag ot troffe na edam syawla I
,I dna kiroR rof hcihw
.nwo ruo no tuo ti ekatS“
.enif gnola tog ew
.dnal-niV .dnalniV
?won yppah uoy erA“ .akleV delrans
.dereuqnoC dna deniarT ohw eH ,nevorP eht kayneK .eltit wen ym fo gnivresed won m’I taht eveileb I
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
,egalliv kukiuR eht ni kcab gnisoohc nwo ym fo stseuqnoc tuo gnikees deirt dah I
.kayaK ,wonk t’nod I“
.hsif eb ylno dluoc tahw fo sliartne eht hguorht sregnif rieht gninnur ,pmal lio na sa
.emoh llac dluoc ew ecalp wen a dnuof ew hcihw snaem eht osla saw ti
.kiroR demrifnoc
.eporuE ni egalliv rieht fo tuo nevird erew sdneirf dna kayneK ,emit tsaL
,lausu sA ”?pU“  .deteerg I ”?kiroR ,pu s’tahW“ .sbmil dna worb sih no nees neeb dluoc sevlas dna segadnab hserF
.tnereffid on si hsif dna ,dlrow eht tuohguorht dellevart dah taht yerp ni dnuof tseb era seicehporp taht
,lairetam roirraw gnieb su yned ot htuom ym denepo I
,taob eht ot esuoherots taht fo tuo su dehsur t’ndah I fI“ .akleV taps
.enecs a sdrawot gnirutseg
feihC eht decnivnoc roirraw neknurd a fo noisserpmi
.deneppah taht gnihtyreve rof em emalb ot gniyrt potS“
”.taht tuoba tbuod oN
”.elpoep ruo htiw ecalp a evah syawla ll’uoy dna ,su niarT“
.kcab deppans akleV
.mih ta detniop sraeps etipsed looc niamer ot sllab tog s’etam ruoy timda ot evah uoy ,lriG“
.tseb sih did kayneK ,akleV“
,revewoh reh ot pu ti edam I
.nopu gnizag neeb dah I tahw ot kcab ezag ym denrut I
,egalliv retnuhelahW eht dekoolrevo taht gol a nopu tas I
.yerp rof hcraes ro levart fo snaem a sa
.enas em peek ot tsyrt lanoisacco eht htiw
.morf detcive neeb dah
.devil elpoep dias dah aderG erehw fo tsaoc eht ffo teef 002 tuoba erew ew emit eht yb gnineve etal saw tI
.sevitan dnalneerG eht htiw emoh wen rieht fo tuo nevird erew yeht ,retal shtnoM
s’kiroR ,ti evah dluow kcul sA
”.kayneK ,uoy evol I“ .kcil a em evag akleV
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer