.goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”?thgin eht fo dnah tsal eht yalp su evah d’uoy“
.egaP lanoitidda na saw rehtieN
,thgil ssalg deniats htiw ezalba swodniw ,suoromalg dna mirt
.dewob ,neeb evah ot thguo ecaf eht erehw ti evoba dednepsus ksam a htiw ,mrofinu s’pohlleb ytpme nA
,dehsulb lerriuqs eht ”…ylno saw I“
,segnih tneb no rehtegot demmaj
?gnidih sdrac laer eht fo tser eht erew erehW
”.gnineve eht rof ,ereht tseug lanosrep ym uoy ekam ot yppah naht erom eb d’I detseretni er’uoy fI“
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer
”!dnuor siht uoy ot dnasuoht ytnewt
.sefas denoihsaf-dlo lareves fo eno dekcolnu ,eciffo na ot revo mih denokceb lesaew eht ”,ylsuoires yreV“
,klof roop morf ,gnilaets sraey suorepsorp dna gnol tneps dah sicnarF woh cinori ylrettib saw tI
”,ruoy laecnoc ot evil ot decrof neeb ev’uoy seil eht lla noitnem ot ton
.spil sih dekcil eH .gnihtyreve
”.esuoH eht fo retsaM eht sa“
,dekcoldap dna deniahc woN
”.dlofderdnuh a derdnuh hcae hctam ot decrof saw I ,degnellahc eht sa dnA“
,truoC eileesnU eht
.htimS niatnuoM eht
”?ydob ym teb I od“ ,maets detnecs eht otni dehtaerb lerriuqs eht ”,tniop tahw tA“
:yojne yam uoy neht
,teef sih ot esor eH
.dekramer lesaew eht ”,edis llams eht no tib A“
”,seef etal teg dluow stneilc os krowrepap hsinif ot detiaw I“
,teb ylbativeni sicnarF ecnO
.ot dediced d’eh erus saw eh erofeb plug a gnikat flesmih dnuof sicnarF
,yralubatsnoc eht htiw tnemeergasid tneuqesbus eht dna ,sdnob esoht gnivlovni tnedicni elbatterger ehT
,egarekorb eht ta rotnem sih nehw ,dellacer sicnarF ,oga sraey xis ylraen neeb dah tI
.rood tnorf eht sa P dna K denworc emas eht htiw demmargonoM
,hcaorppa ot yrt uoy fi taht eerga selat eht lla tuB
.gnihton t’nsaw secA owt ,llitS
saw taht tops hcihw susnesnoc on saw ereht—
”!ti ni daorba deklaw I tsal ecnis hcum taht degnahc evah tonnac dlrow ehT“
d’eh won ecno naht erom dnA
”.wonk enoyna tel t’ndluoc I fi neve
.elkcusyenoh daed dna tsur fo sessam sselepahs won ,sadnarev nori thguorw fo seirots eerhT
.suoregnad neve dna
.namssenisub derit a fo lward detartsurf ehT
,yb ssap tiusrup tel ot ,edih ot ecalp a ylno was eno sihT
.dexiffa neeb ecno dah evoba nworc a htiw P dna K latipac a fo margonom a erehw fo ngis ylno eht gnirehtew ressel fo wodahs a
?yticapac rehtona ni rentrap ym gnieb fo ronoh eht em od dluow uoy fI
.deneppah dah detcepxenu gnihtemos fi sa dekool esuoH eht fo retsaM eht ,emit tsrif eht roF ”.dlof ot evah I“
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.nwog gnisserd a no deppils lesaew ehT
”?derdnuh owt regaw I“
.sladnacs ytirbelec ro ,anemonehp lamronarap ro ,stnuoc ydob htiw seno
.rood eht yb retiawbmud a morf sehciwdnas tnasaehp ynit dna
tnemmoc tuohtiw detneserp
,ylneddus kcab deppans noitnetta s’sicnarF nehw gniyas saw esuoH eht fo retsaM ehT ”?noitidreP
.yllufepoh dias sicnarF
.pihc onisac denoihsaf dlo na saw detcepsus eh tahw dna
,ylhtooms dias lesaew eht ”,wonk uoy ,nac uoY“
”.dnah rehtona rof ni uoy yub ll’taht dna
.nosaer on rof gnihtyna fo elur tsrif eht t’nerew sgniht …llits tuB
.yenom sih kcab teg ot gniyrt ,niw ot gniyrt
,smra s’retsaM eht otni flesmih desserp eh sa derepsihw sicnarF ”,evah ll’I“
.detinuer neeb ro detrap evah dluow srelevart erehw ,ni kcehc ot detiaw evah dluow elpoep erehw si siht ,saw ti revetahW
”.ereht dnuor txen eht rof slasoporp ssucsid nac eW“
.sekoj ytrid fo telkoob gnisuma na erew yeht ekil meht tcepsni ot sdrac sih tuo dennaf ylitnuaj retsaM ehT
,sselthginK erew gniK dna neeuQ ym ,sala tub ,ylimaF layoR a rof hguone ward dluow I erus saw I“ .dehgual lesaew eht ”,dneirf ym uoy htiw si kcul ,yhW“
”?eciohc ruoy si tahw
,taorht sih deraelc esuoH eht fo retsaM eht ”,dias I“
…tuB“ ,sdrac sih pord ot ton deirt dna dekaeuqs sicnarF ”!?tahw -ytnewT“
.swodniw hgih htiw mid
,meht ksa ot ytinutroppo neeb ereht daH  floWcaM boR yb
,nihc sih rednu sserac eltneg a htiw taht detautcnup dah lesaew eht dezilaer sicnarF emit eht yB
a sulp ,dnasuoht dlofdnasuoht a gninniw fo thguoht sicnarF
”.dneirf ym ,emag siht ta suoicorta era uoy ,ylurt tuB
.deb eht drawot mih degdun sicnarF
”.niaga uoy hctam llahs I dnA“
,stuobaerehw tnerruc sih no noitamrofni yna sah wonk uoy enoyna ro uoy fI
.decnavda yllacigolonhcet oot elttil a saw ,demees ti ,etteluor nevE
:seiretsym gninwaps-noissesbo suomaf esoht fo eno emaceb reven rettam ehT
”!nar dna lla ti tpek I ,erahs sih revo gnidnah fo daetsni neht dnA“
,detcepxe d’eh naht retsaf elttil a tnew lrihw a sa tsehc s’lesaew eht tsniaga gnignilc flesmih dnuof sicnarF ”,erus ton m’I“
.erolklof lacol lufroloc etaicerppa ot emit sah modles evitiguf a tuB
.sevlesmeht gnitacixotni ylisub ,gnittahc sremotsuc deleeh-llew fo swor dna ,rednetrab eht fo kcab eht denigami tsuj evah tsum eH .lla s’tahT
a ot del rood rehtonA
-selbbub eht htiw dexim dah htaerb sih
.yawa klaw uoy llit gnihtyna tsol t’nevah uoy si rekop fo elur tsrif“
.ruf sih tub gnihtyna raew ot deen on tlef eh dnuof sicnarF tuB
”sdnomaiD fo evanK sekaT selcatneP fo gniK“
.pu denut dnab eht sa ylthgirb gnirettahc
tsol dah sicnarF ,ruoh rehtona nihtiW
.revo meht dessap retsaM ehT ”!sdrac owT
.engapmahc fo etsat eht htiw evila llits saw htuom s’lerriuqs eht elihw now d’eh ssik eht tcelloc neht dna
.detnuah saw ecalp siht mih llet ot selat 'slacol yna dedeen regnol on eH
.rethgit kcapkcab eht dehctulc sicnarF
.ruf keehc sih hguorht htaerb mraw tlef sicnarF litnu ylevitseggus repsihw ot hguone esolc werd retsaM eht ”,evolg a ro kcos a gniregaw ekil tsuj s’ti ,yhW“ ”.dnatsrednu I“
’sdnob nelots ni sdnasuoht derdnuh-ruof-
”.evael ot ytinutroppo na evah I nehw …no dneped lliw tI .wonk
,rehto eht ni kced eht ,dnah eno ni ssalg engapmahc eht dah esuoh eht fo retsaM eht ”,ti si erehw dnA“
”.regaw ruoy hctam dna“ ,dias lesaew deksam eht ”,sdrac owt ekat llahs I“
”,dneirf ym ,hguone elpmis s’ti ,yhW“
.dekrow htam gnitteb siht woh dootsrednu eh depoh dna ,desoppus eh ssik
.esnopser ni selleb gnuoy fo kcolf a fo gnirettit eht
:tneculsnart ylthgils yrev
”!dnasuoht a yas ll’I“
,sdrawkcab roolf elohw eht derolpxe dah eh rof ,yltsaL
.tuoba kniht dluoc eh lla saw lesaew eht fo etsat eht fo tnih a naht erom gnitnaW
,ksam sih dniheb morf egreme ot hguone worbeye elgnis a desiar lesaew eht ”…rO“
dna dekrow gniht gnitteb-nis siht woh tuo derugif eh litnu owt ro dnah a esol ot detcepxe eh ,thgirla saw hcihW
”,neht ,deerg sa taht tnuocca ll’eW“
,dnah s’lesaew eht morf dedeehnu llef seerhT dna secueD fo tnemtrossa elbakramernu na
.eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo tnemevom was eh
.selcatneP fo gniK ,sevarG fo neeuQ
…yrots eritne na llaf ot tuoba saw eh noitanicullah a saw siht lla fi oS ?dlrow laer ehT
.laed ot mih ot kced eht dessap dna ,lesaew eht dennirg ”!elbarimdA“
.nepo saw ti nehw desu evah dluow yeht drow revetahW .noolas a rO
ecnaraeppasid sih deziroeht tsacdop on ,yratnemucod emirc eurt a no derutaef reven saw erutcip s’sicnarF
,sdnomaid fo enin eht ,drac gniyalp a dnuof d’eH
”?uoy llac I od tahw ,tub ,erus ,hU“
.meht fo eno sserp ot eslupmi eht tsiser t’ndluoc sicnarF tub ,gnissim erew syek eht fo tsoM
.tniop siht ta eriter ot dehsiw uoy fi“ ,sffuc sih detsujda esuoH eht fo retsaM eht ”,uoy emalb ton dluow I“
”?rovaf uoy od semag tahw“
,efil sih dedne eugitaf dna yenom nelots eht lla pu desu d’eh litnu
?reyof a dellac uoy tahw siht saW
.ssalg derahs rieht dellifer dna dehgual lesaew ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot
”?I evah ,ydaerla deerg ruoy lla tuo denaelc t’nevah I“
.sessol sih kcab niw dna draug ffo
.sreyalp rehto eht ta gnikool diova ot tseb sih did sicnarF dna
,nettirwdnah yltnagele neeb dah
.owt ro pets a dednecsed eh sa teprac deyarf eht revo deppirt ylraen eh dna ,mid saw dnoyeb moor ehT
,stseug lacirotsiha ylbissopmi fo seitrap erew selbat rehto eht dnuora deretsulC
.selur eht nialpxe ot deirt eh sa redloh etteragic a gnirahs saw ehs mohw htiw
,riaper tcefrep ni won ,yawriats dnarg eht pu mih denokceb lesaew eht ”,ereh yticapac ym ni ,nwonk ma I“
.niw ot gniyrt eb ot desoppus saw eh taht ecno naht erom flesmih dnimer ot yrassecen ti dnuof sicnarF
.reyof eht fo srenroc tnatsid eht ni derevoh yaced won neve hguoht
:syad yrolg sti ni dekool evah tsum ti sa ,letoh dehsilomed dlo eht ees llits thgim uoy neht ,thgin sselduolc ,sselnoom a no—
,raeh ot raf yrev hcaer ot evah t’ndid noitanigami tub
engapmahc fo tsuj ton detsat ti ,elbainednu tub ,ddo saw ti dnA
,flesmih knird a koot
.etius s’retsaM eht ni htab suoiruxul eht ni flesmih dnuof sicnarF woh saw hcihW
,selbbub fo yarps eht ni gnissorc sreksihw
.cisum fo eton tsal eht fo ohce eht
,gnittes elbatrofmoc erom siht nI
.devlos reven saw yovnE sicnarF fo esac ehT
,ycaripsnoc tnemnrevog a fo trap saw
revirpu snwot eht rof gnikam saw eh emussa dluow spoc eht
,suoires dna rebmos ylneddus erew sdrow derepsihw s’lesaew eht ”,regaw ot tfel evah uoy gniht ylno ehT“
,hcihw dnal eht demialcer ylwols seert eht dna ,dezilairetam reven tnemecalper a rof neeb dah ereht snalp revetahW
,swodniw hcnerf naht rehtaR
?repsihw evitcudes s’lesaew eht ni worros nrolrof fo ecart a ereht saW
?siht fo yna htiw od ot desoppus eh saw tahW ?sgniW fo ecA
.sdrac sih ta dekool eh emit eht yb ,htob meht tuoba ylesool depparw nwog gnisserd eht ,ylleb tfos ,rednels s’lesaew eht no daeh sih ,pu delruc saw eh os dnA
”?dlof ot evah I kniht I“
!dnah a now yllanif eh ecno ,yhtlaew ylenecsbo eb ot gniog saw eH
?nrecnoc eht saw tahw os ,esoht fo yna dah regnol on eh ,yhw ,nis a saw os gniod fI
”!tsixe t’ndid taht ynapmoc saesrevo na ni serahs dlos I“
.dnah eht gnisol htrow neeb evah thgim siht detseggus ylsuorehcaert
.on ro sekats desiar ,dnah eht tsol llits sicnarF
,yaw tnorf eht ni emoc ot deen on dah eH
.nosirp rehtona tey ni efil taht fo tser eht gnidneps ro
,raivac ,eiretucrahc
,tsol d’eh tsul eht yb detcartsid ,tsol d’eh deerg eht yb derul oS
,flesmih deird ,htab eht fo tuo deppets sicnarF sa
,emit emas eht ta knird htob meht tel ot edis eht ot ti pit ot deganam wohemos ,meht neewteb ssalg eht desiar ,sicnarF ot esolc ecaf sih tneb eh
.semag on ,secnad on ,cisum on saw ereht erehw nosirp A
,yovnE sicnarF eno fo swen eht htiw detadpu yltnecer tsoM
,regaw uoY“ .elbatrofmoc ylgnilttesnu saw ,tsiaw sih dnuora mra sih dna redluohs s'lerriuqs eht no dnah sih ekil ,elims s’esuoH eht fo retsaM eht
,eugnot sih revo dehsaw dah eniw emas eht ,oot ti dehcuot dah spil elbaturcsni sih wonk oT
”!tahw rettam on ,emos neht dna kcab lla ti niw uoy
yenom eht tog eh llit stohs gnikat peek ot dedeen tsuj eh ,ygetarts htiw lleh ot hO
.traeh sih gnisol dna gnitteb
.tfeht ti dellac yeht woN
,ni detsixe regnol on
”!gnicnad s’gnineve siht denepo I emit si tI
!kcab ti now eh ecno yenom sih ot ylppa ot evah ot gniog saw esuoH eht fo retsaM eht sdlofderdnuh ynam woh no seye sih peek tsuJ
”?yrgnuh er’uoy eb ti dluoC
”!dnik a fo eerhT“ ”.em rof sdrac oN“
.ereht llits tub ,dedorroc hcum htob erew kcab eht ta rorrim suorednop eht dna mottob eht
,sthgil eht nwod nrut dna
”sdnomaiD fo evanK sekaT selcatneP fo gniK“ saw sihT
”!emit siht degnellahc era uoy ,tnedifnoc-revo emoceb ton oD .dneirf ym ,emag siht rof tnelat a evah uoy mees dluow tI“
?nlednamhortS ?sorG xuaraT“
.detnuah deredisnoc saw sdoow eht ni kcab niur dlo eht dias evah dluow slacol
,mih tuoba gnikniht ralloc eht rednu toh teg dluow I esuac wal eht gnikaerb otni em klat ssob ym tel ylno I tcaf eht ,hu ,esiar I“
,sicnarF dettimda dah wodniw hcnerf despalloc eht hcihw otni ,moor siht spahreP
,tor yrd htiw depraw erew sdraob doowdrah eht ,deretne d’eh erehw swodniw eht morf saw thgil ylno ehT ?llah teuqnab a rO
”?esimorp srehcaerp eht fo sehcruhc eht tahw ton taht sI
.deretne d’eh moor eht revo eninazzem fo tros a otno ,smoor gnimag eht fo dne rehto eht ot retsaM eht dewollof d’eH ”.snis ruoy regaw“
”.evael ot ytiliba ruoy si“
,ees em tel ,sekam tahT
,straeH fo thginK ,sdnomaiD fo evanK ,spuC fo egaP
.delkcuhc lesaew eht ”,deedni era erehT“
.htimS niatnuoM eht
!yrotsih ni nosrep tsehcir eht eb d’eH
,erusaem suoreneg a deruop eh ”,em nioj ll’uoy epoh od I“
,ti dettimmoc dah eh won ,erus eh saw roN
,keehc tsniaga keehc
,delttes srood fo tes A
,hsurb dna seltsiht lla won ,nwal yletats A
.dehgual dna daeh sih kcab werht esuoH eht fo retsaM ehT
.detnaw esle ydobon ,llet dluoc yeht sa raf os
.llaf ecaf sih tlef sicnarF
.ecalp tsrif eht ni nur eht no mih tes dah taht duarf laicnanif xelpmoc fo eceip tnecer tsom eht otni mih klat nam eht tel evah dluohs eh taht
.regnif sih detfil eh nehw nwod deyats ti dna
erutcurts eritne siht esuaceb ,rood eht hguorht toof tes tsrif eh nehw ,tbuod gnippots-traeh fo tnemom a neeb dah erehT
.nageb cisum ecnad denoihsaf-dlo eht sa skool gniwonk ylbatrofmocnu wef a naht erom tlef dah sicnarF
,ogitrev lanoitome fo dnik emos ,egnarts yldnuoforp tlef osla eH
.deppord waj s’sicnarF
.gnihtemos niw yllanif d’eh sepoh eht ni dnah eht hsinif ot detnaw tsuj eh ,gnirewsna tuoba kniht ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc sicnarF
,reverof ,gnipacse erom tub ot gnipacse rehtie evas
.onaip thgirpu na fo llehs wolloh eht tas renroc eht nI
.sregnif owt desiar dna denrut retsaM eht ,dnah txen eht tlaed sicnarF sA
dednecsed ytiralc suonigitrev ,dloc A
”,lleW .did I esoppus …I“
.ffo mih daeh dna yrt ot ereht ecar dna—ton saw tub
,etiteppa railimaf tub yawanur ylgninekcis emos fo ,seye sih deworran lesaew eht nehw ,tlef eh egniwt tniaf eht dnim reveN
?ereht neeb syawla taht dah ,tiaW
.edisa meht tes dna rehtegot sdrac sih dils lerriuqs eht ,hgis peed a htiW
.koobtseug egral a denepo dah lesaew ehT
.edisni dekool dna deppots eh ,niaga nehctik eht dessap eh sA
.kcab eltrats ot etal oot ydaerla saw ti
.ti bmilc ot yaw a dnif ot elba eb ot thguo lerriuqs yna dna
,staoc gnineve elbaccepmi
”.enola hguone llew gnivael ni emahs on si ereht dna ,htiw ni deklaw uoy tahw fo flah spahrep tsol ev’uoY
”!emehcs iznop no-lluf a pu tes ssob ym depleh I“
.naelc erew ti no dial noops dna krof ehT
secalp ot railucep ssenitpme gnimool fo seiceps taht htiw dednuoser letoh tcilered ehT
.moor ytsum siht ni neve ,ti no regnil ot deganam eniw dlo eht fo llems eht woh ynnacnU
,ragic gnillems-luof a dnuora dias d’eh ”,diK“
,spoc eht rof hctaw peek ot ecalp doog a spahrep
.lla ta ton mih deyamsid ygetarts siht fo eruliaf eht ,ylsuoiruC
.sriatsnwod noillim owt naht erom evah did eh ,llew ”,hU“
.ssalg elgnis a morf engapmahc fo elttob a gnirahs ,rehtona eno dnuora smra ,enodnu seit
?thgir ,doog eb ot dah dnik a fo eerhT
.dekcolnu eno dnuof eh llit modnar ta srood esohc eH
.krow ti ekam nac ew yaserad I tub ,eno tnecer ylevitaler a s’taht“ ,gnilaed ydaerla saw lesaew eht ”,lleW“
ekat nac dnuor elgnis a dna ,sreyalp erom deen d’ew tub ,edistuO tfeL naM htruoF syawla s’erehT
,ffo tuhs neeb dah ti retfa dnoces tilps eht rekaepsduol a morf fi sa
rof deppord traeh s’sicnarF ”-uoy esiar ll’I dna ,uoy hctam ll’I !tirips eht s’tahT“
”?gnitteb eht gninepo fo ronoh eht em od uoy dluoW
”.deen t’ndid yeht snaol tneduts gnikat otni nemhserf egelloc gniklat tneps raey eht regaw ll’I“
:seiretsym gnitseretni erom derreferp elpoeP
.skao evil fo evorg a yb delcricne
.sriats eht dednecsed gnineve eht rof rentrap sih dna esuoH eht fo retsaM eht sa yletilop dedualppa dna pu dekool dah yehT
”?thgin eno naht erom su htiw gniyats eb uoy lliW“
”?noitaxaler fo tnemom a rof sllac siht kniht I“
!lla si ,em desirprus teb ruoy ,llew“
’,maerc eci reh erahs t’ndluow ehs nehw ,sliatgip s’retsis ym dellup I emit eht‘ ,yas
.neppah taht tel d’eh ylisae woh ta esaenu delffab a dna
,ruf sih hguorht sregnif gninnur
.snoitca sih fo ytilarom eht no
.tnagavartxe elttil a eb ot droffa dluoc eh desoppus sicnarF
.yromem lartsecna ruo ni
,srednepsus sih dna skcos sih neewteb erehwemos ,dellacer ylmid eH
?moor aet A ?rolrap
.der fo edahs emos
,gnihton rof liaj ot og ot gniog saw eh won ,gnikniht neeb eh dah tahw ,yenom eht lla tsol d’eh woh tuoba ,daeh sih ni smaercs eht revo klat ot deirt eh ”,trap eht siht sI“
.llet a neeb evah ylniatrec dluow rehtegot esolc desserp deniamer dah stsiaw rieht fi leef ot elba neeb evah dluow lesaew eht tahw dnA
,stavarc ni setoyoc dna snwog gnineve ni stacbob ,staocliat ni syaj eulb dna strikspooh ni stibbaR
.roolf rehto yna sa yldilos sa thgiew sih enruob dah ti tub
.retsaM sih morf ssik peed rehtona tpecca ot daeh sih denrut eh sa ,thguoht sicnarF ,sgniht wef a denialpxe hcihW
.sllet yawa evig ot ton ,erus ytterp saw eh ,gnilbmag ni tnatropmi saw tI
?huh ,evael ot ytiliba siH
”?ton reveyhW .esruoc fO“
?snroht fo evlewT
.ssalg deniats saw gnihtyreve ereh
.sih tsniaga ruf tfos oN
.rekorb tnemtsevni na regnol on erew uoy ylnedduS
.derised oS .rof deregnuh os tlef efil sih ni reven d’eH
.mra gnitivni na tuo dleh eH
”!gnihtemos htrow s’taht
,sgnir dna ,sdrows ,straeh ,stiurf fo ssem elbisneherpmocni eht ta delwocs eh ”,hU“
stsiaw eripme ni sdaot
yas ot dnim sih pu edam d’eh elbat eht ta taes sih demialcer sicnarF emit eht yb taht ,lla retfa ,hguone evisausrep saw hcihW
.ot dnetta ot seitud rehto emos evah I tsrif tub“
’srekcus-egasuas‘ dna ’sresiar-liat‘ tuoba sekoj suoicilam hguone ekam rotnem sih draeh d’eh tuB
.snehctik eht neeb ecno evah tsum siht demuserp eh dnoyeb ssenkrad eht otni pag eht hguorht gnireep retfa tub
.lesaew eht dias ”.uoy rof moor ruoy ot pu nekat eb lliw gab ruoY“
.daetsni sllaw eht ta dekool sicnarF oS
?moorllab a neeb ecno dah
.sessik oN .mih gnirised seye gninrub oN
”.yadhtrib s’tsinoitpecer eht rof etubirtnoc ot desoppus s’enoyreve nehw epolevne eht otni gnihtyna tup reven I“
”?luos ym teb ot em ksa uoy erehw“
?snis rieht fo dir eb ot gniyrt sevil elohw rieht dneps“
,edis sih ta saw mrofinu s'retiaw deksam ytpme na yltnatsnI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ssalg kcalb fo telbog elgnis a dna
,yek a gnidloh flesmih dnuof sicnarF
sih sa hcus sgniht htiw ,eceip yb eceip ,gnihtolc sih gnitteb fo ygetarts eht deirt eh
.yticificeps erom htiw ekops selatklof lacol esoht won spahrep hguohT .detnuah erew sdoow eht ni sniur dlo eht yas ot deunitnoc selatklof lacol ,elihw eht llA
.elbissop sa citamard sa ,pot eht morf gnidnecsed eno dna mottob eht ta eno neewteb ,tcatnoc eye tsrif fo tnemom eht ekam ot tnaem ylnialp saw ,desum sicnarF ,esacriats ehT
.yalp ot mih thguat dah ,acro na fo dratsab tnagorra na
,ssalg elgnis rehtona ,engapmahc fo elttob rehtona ot flesmih depleh lesaew eht ”,ytsenoh lla nI“
,yalp ot woh wonk ot ton gnidneterp saw lwahs egnirf dna sserd reppalf keels a ni hcnifdlog A
.moor rehtona morf eciov a draeh
”.evael ot ytiliba ruoy tsniaga ,ecalp siht ot thguorb uoy enutrof eht dlofderdnuh A“
,spil sih ot puc eht esiar ,elbat eht ssorca nael ot lesaew eht rof ysae yllaivirt ti edam hcihW
”tol a adnik …s’tI“
tey t’nod I“ ,5491 detad saw sih dengis sicnarF erehw enil eht evoba eman txen eht ”,hu ,I“
naht yletarucca erom desseug eb ot roloc lanigiro rieht rof dedaf-nus oot ,sniatruc derettat erew erehT
.ot nur ot esle ecalp emos dnif tsum eh erofeb peels fo htrow s’thgin a teg yllufepoh ot
,flesti ecalp eht ot emoc uoy fi
.moor siht ni dnuof eb ot enon erew ereht tub ”oknihcap“ ebyam ro ”,senihcam tols“ rewsna ot dekil evah dluow sicnarF
.tuo mih dnif egarekorb eht tel reven dluoc eh wonk ot
.desoppus eh ,edistuo eht morf redluohs s’enoyna revo gnikool enoyna evah ot od t’ndluoW
,emag eht tuoba lla tegrof ot deganam eh ,knard sicnarF sA
.roolfecnad teuqrap dehsilop a no woleb tuoba dellim ,yrenif desufnoc yllacirotsih erom ni ,dworc llams A
,emad ednarg decneirepxe dna duorp a fo hgual yssarb ehT
.elbat eht ssorca ecilahc eht dessap neht
,irauR nosmirC yb daeR  .yrellag yrruFoS sih no ti ekil erom dnif nac uoy dna
.selbmahs nerrab a llits ,oN
”!dneirf ym ,si ssik a tahw wonk tsum uoy yleruS“ ”?tahw A“ ”.ssik A“ ,tnemom a
.sadnarev roolf dnoces eht fo eno dniheb tes
.sdnaW fo egaP eht ,sgniR fo egaP ehT
…senob yrev ruoy llihc ot elat a si siht rof
detsujda seye sih nehW
”!derdnuh owt teb ylno I thguoht I
.sdrac sih ta kool ot nettogrof d’eh dezilaer sicnarF
!timmad ,kcab yenom eht dedeen eH
esuoH eht fo retsaM eht hctac thgim taht semit ta ni nworht etiteppa sih ro erised
.moordeb eht ot kcab esuoH eht fo retsaM eht dewollof
”.dne eht ni ,sniw syawla esuoh eht em dlot uoY“
,llew sa klof hcir morf gnilaets fo tnemtsujda thgils yrev eht edam uoy nehw taht
”?gnineve eht fo tser eht tnemesuma tuohtiw su evael dna ,tahW“
ta liar ssarb ehT .yleritne moor eht fo edis eno derevoc taht rab suomrone na saw erehT
.tsael ta railimaf saw eno tahT
”.seca owt tog ev’I ,hU“
,odexut yerg eht ni xof eht fo tnemesuma eht ot hcum
,engapmahc fo ssalg rehtona ruop esuoH eht fo retsaM eht gnihctaw ,eno txen eht gnilaed morf detcartsid tog nehT
gninetsil er’uoY
,tfel tib elttil a tsuj dah eh epoh derad eh tub taht fo ytnelp
.deplug lerriuqs eht
,tcepxe ot gnihton dah eh erehw ,dlrow elbaresim ,yerg ,dloc eht ni tuO
”?derdnuh rehtona regaw ll’I“
”?tseug wen a ,llew
,pu kcab doots eh nehW
dehgual sicnarF ”?tahW“
.ecarg dna ecnedifnoc htiw meht dednecsed dah lesaew eht tub ,sicnarF ot yhtrowtsurtnu demees dah sriats ehT ”.esruoc fO“
.ti no kcul sih sserp dluoc eh fi ,elihw a ni dah d’eh dnah gnikool tseb eht saw siht …tuB
,plug gnillor-taorht gnol a ekat
.mih tsniaga niw ot elba neeb reven dah sicnarF ,esruoc fO
.yawa detirips era ohw esoht tuoba seirots evah serutluc tsoM
.niaga nees reve saw elots eh yenom eht ron eh rehtieN
,ssik eht tsdima tsol ,dnim sih fo renroc A
mih ot gnoleb t’ndid gnileef saw eh noitanimreted eht fi sa
”.nrael ot emit fo ytnelP“
,eldnac eht erew eh dna thgil gnirekcilf a erew tsap eht fi sa ,mih dnuora evila emoc dah moor ehT
?tuohtiw eno naht retteb spil s’lesaew emosdnah a no engapmahc fo etsat eht htiw deilppus ylpma nosirp a t’nsaW
.lacidohtem eb ot tseB
?tneserp eht ,llew
.rethgual gnitallitnics dna cisum ecnad denoihsaf dlo htiw gniohce
,ksed tnorf eht no nepo ti daerps eh nehw dna pu ti dekcip dah eh emit eht neewteb nI
”?edam evah ew regaw eht dootsrednu evah uoY“
”.wonk uoy ,yllautneve sniw syawla esuoh eht yas yehT“
.doof elbidercni dah ti ,saw ecalp siht esle revetahW
.neeb dah snis sih tahw wenk ydaerla esuoH eht fo retsaM eht woh rednow ot tegrof ot hguone drah dehsulb tsomla sicnarF
.sriatsnwod efas a ni kcapkcab a ni
.enitsirp ylpsirc ot ,trapa gnillaf dna ytsud morf enog dah segap eht
,toh gnihtemos htiw puc ruoy llif
.rood eht drawot kcab ylsuoicipsus denrut sicnarF
.sih sa mir eht no tops emas eht hcuot dluow spil s’lerriuqs eht os ssalg eht reffo yletarebiled dna
.ssenneddus gnimrala htiw denrecnoc semoceb wal eht
,edisni saw kcapkcab sih ecnO
,ksam sih fo seloh eht hguorht decnad seye s’lesaew eht ”,spahrep ,yticirtnecce nA“
fo yart revlis a thguorb ohw ,revres motnahp rehtona denommus retsaM eht rewsna sih rof gnitiaw tuohtiW
?eb eh dluohs yhW
”!neht ,si ti dlofderdnuh A“
,alopuc a htiw rewot A
gnihtemos osla tub—
.rettub dna eniw ni deetuas gnieb snoino dellems d’eh dnoces a rof nrows ev’dluoc eh teY
.derutnev sicnarF ”?sdrac eerht ekat I nac …hU“
sih tey saw taht kcul fo revils emos tub ,hsulf layor a yltcaxe t’nsaw tI
”.reverof tuo snur kcul s’ydoboN“
,nugeb dah cisum eht dna smra sih ni yleruces saw sicnarF ecno ,derepsihw lesaew eht ”,syawla dluoc uoY“
.derolpxe ylhguoroht neeb dah ydob sih fo hcni yreve litnu ,ylwols
.evah tsum ti esruoc fo …tuB
,srolrap eerht fo tes a eb ot devorp dah smoor gnimag ehT
.rab a neeb dah siht tnedifnoc tlef eh
,stius eceip-eerht ni star dna
.elbat eht ssorca mrofinu yrlavac eulb-etals eht ni
.letoh dehsilomed dna denodnaba na ot detcennoc reve eh saw ron
.giw deredwop a dna esoh thgit ni nibor a etisoppo
ytnewt‘ hcihw no pils mialc a
.egrahc cirtcele na ekil tlef edisni sdnob ni noillim ruof tniop owt nelots ehT
engapmahc lanoitpecxe dna—
?uoy nettog reve snis ruoy evah tahw“
:ynoclab tsehgih eht no serugif owt ees thgim uoy yas neve emoS
.meht fo htob rof ,niaga engapmahc fo ssalg elgnis a gniruop saw retsaM ehT
.ecnartne eht neeb evah tsum tahw saw
.niaga ti delffuhs dna kced eht deveirter lesaew ehT
,esruoc fo ,tluser oN
,ksam onimod lufetsat dna sserd gnineve elbaccepmi eht ni ,esacriats dnarg eht fo pot eht ta yltcefrep demarf ,lesaew eht dias ”,lleW“ .tcerroc devorp saw hcihW
?sefas ruo fo eno ni ti ecalp yam uoy“
.srood yna gniyrt erofeb dne eht ot yaw eht lla tnew eH
emos neht dna noillim owt gnittup pu dedne taht snalp tuoba gniklat detrats dah rotnem dlo sih nehw nettog d’eh ekil
.eno morf ffo raf t’nsaw ti mih dlot
erew erehT .reerac remrof sih fo stib tsenohsid dna evitatiolpxe gnitteb peek dna daeh looc a peek ot dah tsuJ
.esruoc fo ,dehsilomed yllautneve saw letoh dlo ehT
tekcub gnillihc a ni engapmahc fo elttob a htiw
.nwo t’ndid eh sgniht htiw elbatrofmoc saw sicnarF
!sneves fo riap a ylno evah I
,mih gnidausrep eunitnoc ot kcab denrut flah smoor gnimag eht drawot kcab sriats eht koot retsaM eht ”,tsom ton oD“
”.tseug a dah ev’ew ecnis deedni emit gnol a neeb s’tI“
.noitadnuof deniur eht fo skcarc eht hguorht gniworg sgnilpas kao evil dna seltsiht tub dnif ot ereht gnihton si ereht
,denraw neeb evah dluoc eh erehw seno eht—
?ton yhw esuaceb ,lla retfa luos sih teb eh ,tsol saw stnemragrednu sih fo tsal eht ecnO
.mih ta dennirg lesaew ehT
nooccar gums eht ta sreggad deralg riah lrig nosbig fo tnemidep dna eltsub a ni mussop a
,floWcaM boR yb ”sdnomaiD fo evanK sekaT selcatneP fo gniK“
.ecalp eht denwo eh ekil
?gnol yenruoj ruoy saW
.elttob engapmahc a morf kroc a
,luos sih nwo ot lesaew eht rof snevele fo riap s'lerriuqs eht ot sthgink eerht dna sevif owt nwod gniyal naht erom on koot ti dna ”,lleW“
.erehwemos wodniw nepo na eb dluow ereht tub
.detatiseh lerriuqs eht ”?ssalg eno eht tsuJ“
.esol dna ,yalp ot gnilliw saw eh nosaer laer eht ssefnoc ot elba neeb reve eh dah roN
.tsol sicnarF gniht txen eht saw
”.setiteppa citnamor“
…htiw knird a erahs ot yaw retteb tahW .gnineve elbacima erom hcum a rof sekam ti leef I tub“
.epacse ot ,nur ot ,dlrow eht ni tuo kcab eb oT
,rood elbuod dnarg a fo sbals taerg owT
tops thgir eht morf dekool uoy fi yas dluow emoS
.gnihton od ot elba devorp eh hcihw htiw ,sdrac sih mih tlaed retsaM eht
.morf emoc dah ti erehw aedi on dah sicnarF
.lortnoc rednu flesmih teg dna yawa nrut ot ecnahc a dah sicnarF os ,dualppa ot detarapes lla roolf eht no selpuoc eht dna ereht dedne dnab eht yllufknahT
?sdrows fo eviF ?gnidloh eh saw lleh eht tahW
”esoht fo yna wonk t’nod I diarfa m’I“
pu desu dah eh dna ,kcul yna htiW
”?smoor gnimag era erehT“ .dekrep rae s’sicnarF
,oot tsul dna ,ssenlufhturtnu ,hA“
.spuC dna ,sthgiL ,sratS ,straeH ,sdnomaiD fo neveS eht nwod dial dna dennirg esuoH eht fo retsaM eht ”,diarfa m’I ,dnik a fo eviF“
.od ot mih rof gnitiaw saw retsaM eht tahw saw taht fi erusnu gnieb fo tnemom a retfa sdrac sih nwod deppals sicnarF
.yliraw dettimda sicnarF
,anorolL aL ,tnuH dliW ehT
,tlef neerg tfos ni derevoc selbat eht ,wol erew ereh sthgil ehT
peed seog aedi eht :enohpesreP fo htym eht ,noitcudba OFU
,dniheb morf ,ylesolc ,yltneg ,mih gnicarbme saw eh yas ot etarucca erom eb dluow ti hguoht ,mih gnihtab saw lesaew ehT
.emit siht sbulC fo ,ecA rehtona ta gnikool flesmih dnuof lerriuqs ehT
.ytnelp ylniatrec
,nus gnittes fo etsat tsal eht hctac ot gniniarts slliswodniw eht no ssom saw ereht dna ,snoitces ni gnispalloc dna gnileep saw gniliec dessobme ehT ?tnaruatser A
.htiw ti dias evah dluow rotnem remrof sih ssenmrif emas eht rof gniyrt ,dias sicnarF ”,yats ll’I“
”?eriF elbatS ?ogehC dnilB“
.edistuo morf mih ot enod gnieb saw dna
.hguoht ,dnim reveN
”.smoor gnimag eht ta pu tiderc fo enil tnelaviuqe na rof tekcit ruoy tneserp“
.dniheb rehtruf neve llef eh
epip sih ta ylevisnep deffup niahc-hctaw dna taoctsiaw a ni gats A
”.derdnuh a ta trats ll’I“
,yawllah kcab a nwod derednaw eH
?ianiopseD ?spahrep ,avisergorP“
.ssalg eht dniheb deppart hsinrat fo smoolb eht neewteb ni ,flesmih nees evah tsum eH
.ecnereffid eht fo erusnu saw eh ,tcetihcra on saw sicnarF ?muirta na rO
.sdworc fo esion eht dna noitarbelec dna thgil htiw dellif eb ot tnaem
.yawllah rediw a hguorht knuls eh sa delgnit kcen s’sicnarF fo kcab eht no ruf ehT
?wol gninnur wohemos eh saw ,tihs ”…I“
.retrop a fo noisicerp etilop ehT
denoihsaf-dlo ,suoveihcsim ,dliw ,citoxe
.ti tiolpxe ot yaw a dnuof
.nikpan nenil a saw ,sirbed fo raelc wohemos ,selbat eht fo eno no dial tub
.yadyeh sti ni ecalp dnarg a neeb evah dluow letoh ehT
,remaerts lesnit a
.rorrim rab eht ylno saw ti tub ,delrihw eH
yrevocsid lufetaf eht rof ton fi ,erutuf raen eht ni ,flesmih klof hcir neeb evah ylekil d’eH .klof hcir rof
!scitsitats tsuj saw ti ,yllautneve niw d’eh ,teb ot snis dah eh sa gnol sA
.etius etavirp sih ot pu mih gninokceb retsaM eht ot tcejbo ot nosaer yna was regnol on eh ,snis sih lla ,tsol dna
”.wonk uoy ,ylsuoires yrev ytreporp elbaulav ekat I
.thgin eht fo tser eht rof ,tros yna fo noissucsid deedni ron ,revewoh ,semag drac fo noissucsid hcum ton saw erehT
,floWcaM boR yb
?sgninniw ym detcelloc I emit si ti neht“
:thgil eht otni pu ti kcip ot tneb eH
.meht morf noitartnecnoc emos eraps ot spets ecnad eht fo hguone erus saw eh ecno deksa sicnarF ”?snis ym teb nac I ,naem uoy od woH“
,sedapS fo egaP ehT .retteb tol a dnah siht fo kool eht dekil sicnarF ”…yas ll’I“
”?erofeb rekop pirts deyalp ev’uoy yleruS“
”?rekoP fo noisrev a ereht sI“ ”…thgin lla
.yrots eht ot erom on saw ereht dna ,yenom eht htiw yawa teg ot hguone ykcul tog ohw relzzebme na tsuj saw eh ylsuoivbO
nehT“ .deddon sicnarF
.deedni gnineve llud a eb lliw siht esle ro ,suorutnevda erom eb ot nrael ll’uoy epoh od I .ytip a tahw“ ,delkcuhc lesaew ehT ”?ylurt ,hO“
.erofeb ereht neeb t’ndah ylniatrec taht lleb ksed a gnar dna koob eht tuhs eH
,dnatsdnab a neeb evah ecno thgim renroc eht ni sirbed despalloc fo elip eht dna
,erif eht ot resolc emoc ot syas ohw
llit snug ruoy ot kcitS
,hsiruolf lanoisseforp yrev a htiw sdrac fo kced a delffuhs esuoH eht fo retsaM eht ”,oS“