tirips a   sseldrager
,sdrahs eht gnidraoh nugeb dna ekoms eht morf decselaoc nogard a .2
selacs gnicalper neht dna elip a sa   tsrif
.la te Æ yb meop a
,”igustniK“   yojne esaelP
”igustnik“ saw sihT
– tpecnoc levon a tahw .3
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,liat gnihsal ,hteet gnihsang
raj nekorb dnuor‘ gnilioc
gnikcarc rehtruf detceridnu
,relevart wollef ruoy floWcaM boR si sihT
tfos os htrae no hguor oot sdnah
?hguone t’nsaw taht od uoy did tahw os
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
llehs nialecrop sti
selacs ynihs swalc ysmulc .4
ngised lanigiro eht fo elimiscaf a
stnioj dlew wen ,serutcarf sserts wen syawla   htrae war gnidleihs ,eno yb eno
selacs nialecrop neewteb dlog netlom fo
erif emas eht ,htrae emas eht fo er’uoy
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.taoc hcnert a ni snogard lareves fo desopmoc teop a ,.la te Æ yb
skcarc eht morf tuo depees
eruliaf fo sngis etarbelec ot
?ffuts rehguot fo edam uoy t’nera
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
erif eht otni tnew ti
leehw eht nopu ekorb lessev eht .1
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,.la te Æ yb
flesti gnidliuber