.rellortnoc eht demaercs
,dnah ot rehctip tseraen eht debbarg
- revewoh ,awniK ot deneppah noos nonemonehp suoiruc A
flesti dellup erugif eht ereH ”…ma I .thgir llA !thgir llA“  .rehctip eht htiw ylgninetaerht derutseg awniK
.labkA demaercs
,ebirt eht morf dluoc eh egdelwonk eht lla dessama dah awniK nehw oS
”!etageled ot evah reven dna
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
flesym sboj eht lla
,ygolopa na tnaw I“
,gniod s’labkA ni
”.desufnoc kool uoY“
,yretsam latnem siht fo esu edam awniK
.noitcurtsnoc doog fo selpicnirp eht evired ot elba I saw krow ta srehto gnivresbo yb ylerem
”!sehsaleye
,nageb yeht sa noos sa taht
,slobmys kram ot esufer dna
”.pu syats ti taht erusne ot gniog I ma sdog eht yb dna
drah yduts ot devloser eh os
esned os snoitauqe rieht dna
.thgil wolley ni
nòluT fo gniK tsriF eht ,suhT .ni mih tup
ro dimaryp lahpmuirt ruoy ot stnirpeulb eht dnatsrednu dluoc I ylerus
,noitom otni erudecorp siht tup I
erugif derae-ytniop emas eht
?lla ta srekrow ruoy tuoba erac neve uoy oD“
- etamtaes sih ,rorroh sih ot tub ,swen doog eht erahs ot etamtaes sih ot denrut eH
,ylsseltroffe os gnihtyreve seod awniK
awniK taht dlohekohc tsubor eht rof hctam on saw dna
,peels ’sthgin elbirret yrotimrod ym ni enoyreve gnivig era uoY
,etis eht revo llA
,awniK dias ”,uoy era ohW“
nòluT fo ytic eht ot tnew eh
- emit ym etsaw I“ .dereens labkA
gnissap ym nopu oS
,tuo sgniht deklat dna
”?tnaw neve uoy ti si tahW“
,ecnahc eht nevig
.snalp eht dnatsrednu t’ndluoc srosivrepus eht fi srosivrepus evah neve yhw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
s’aziakaerE“  ”.noitanalpxe na ekil dluow“
,erugif eht delley ”!huG“
em naht srebmun dna secidoc htiw retrams enoemos taht enigami tonnac I
.stnetnoc sti htiw mih dehsalps dna
teg woN“ .erugif eht dias
,gnik tneicna rieht fo ronoh ni
”,etairporppa ti ekam t’nseod tahT“
- flesym yb lla rebmahc etavirp ruoy otni yaw a tuo derugif I
tcejorp noitcurtsnoc dnarg rehtona no krabme ot tuoba saw
.tneduts gnuoy eht ta flesmih gnulf eh ,taht htiw dnA
,nwo rieht fo stcejorp wen gnikam erew noos ytterp dna
.yltnatiseh ,awniK dias
- emahs htiw dellif saw awniK
:dediced I taht stnemunom eseht nwod gniraet yenom erom hcum os dneps ot dah I ,dne eht nI
”.flesym uoy evomer ot evah lliw I
.eciov emas eht ni ,dedda edis rehto eht no etamtaes sih ”,seY“
seidob s’trohoc ruoy dna ruoy revo gnikat rof
- dnim s’eno fo snoil eht morf detserw saw hcihw taht si egdelwonk eurt ylno eht rof
.yad eritne eht tnemunom wen eht fo etis eht ot enots deluah dna
.ffo sebor sti llup ot gniyrt elihw lla
,elcyc sruoH fo mooL lluf eht gnidulcni
.awniK dias ”,yrots ylekil A“
”.secifide rednarg rof emas eht od ton dluoc
citemhtira dna gnitirw ni tub
,rellortnoc eht ot pu deotpit
”.elttil a sgnilrednu ruoy tsurT
.tros emos fo lautir gninommus a detutitsnoc
.retsasid wen emos gnikam tuohtiw etis noitcurtsnoc a etagivan ylerab nac yeht taht nees evah ew
.esroh a no snier eht erew yeht fi sa sgnirts tnaig gnillup ylsselerac dna
”?ton reveyhw dnA“
,ecnart railimaf-won eht otni gnillaf flesmih tlef eh sa noos sA
.ecnart sih morf wollef derae-ytniop eht saw
.gniK tsriF eht fo seipoc ton
,seye nailitper htiw erugif derae-ytniop tnelovelam a nopu emac eh
peels peed a otni mih dellul erom ecno serutcel eht dna
.tsael ta yad a rof moor siht ni neeb sah ydoboN“
?rof siht od uoy od gnol woH
!sdaeh s’elpoep ni dnuora gnivohs erom on dnA“ .awniK dias
.derrucco ylurt ti sa ytilaer ees dna
!draobklahc eht no enil retfa enil pu werht
”!ti gnillortnoc eno eht ma I esuaceb dnim ym si tI“
,retaw hserf erom ylppus ot tcudeuqa na ekil
;gninrael s’enoemos fo erusaem eht tsuj ton si lliks rof(
,dnuorg eht no erew nemow dna nem
,laudividni derae-ytniop emas eht fo pu edam sgnag-krow rehto denioj yeht erehw
”reenignE eht dna
”.ti ot dehcatta etiuq ma I esuaceb
”.tnemeerga ro egdelwonk ruoy tuohtiw
.draob eht no smargaid ta gnikool
,dedilloc yeht sa dna ,awniK ta nar eH
”- ezigolopa I“
”.esaelp uoy fi ,oot ,eman ruoy dnA“
.wonk uoy ,sgniht elttil
.thgintrof txen eht revo ylteiuq sessalc gnidneffo eht gnidnetta deunitnoc eh ,dne siht ot dna
sreenigne ruoy ssessop uoy od ,nòluT-fo-gniK-tsriF labkA ,neht yhW“
”!ereht nwod srekrow ynam woh dellik tsomla uoy dna
awniK“   yojne esaelP  .3OA no
,enots fo tuc gnorw eht gniredro
.daeh sih koohs awniK
taruggiz eht fo pot eht morf
wohs ot gniyrt saw ecrof lanretxe na deedni taht
,motsuc egnarts a evah ekaL-wolS fo
- niap desufnoc ni gninaom dna sdaeh rieht gnidloh
.flesmih otni peed tsac dna
;ytivitca htiw gniltsub
”!did uoy tahw eeS“
.mih ot ecitnerppa sretsgnuoy fo lufdnah a evah ot gnieerga yllanoisacco dna ,gnirolpxe
,gnihtyna rof denitsed saw eh ekil demees ti ,yllaeR
,gnikcart dna gnitnuh ni tsuj ton delliks
”,eb em evael dna tuo teg tsuJ“
-“ enot etilop-xuaf ,suoiuqesbo na ni dias ti siht
.ygolopa na raeh t’nod llits I dna“ ,awniK dias
,emit tsal eht rof dehctapsid saw
,ytic eht fo llif sih dah gnivah ,elpoep sih ot denruter dah eh ,awniK rof sA
.teg dluoc yeht pleh eht lla rof yppah saw dna
htnilp a ta detaes
.ytic eht fo strap rewen eht rof metsys rewes regral a ro
srotcurtsni dna stneduts eht sa noitommoc a fo tib a saw ereht
”?era yeht taht sdnim enif eht fo daetsni
,despalloc dah gnidloffacs fo teef fo snezod
meht fo lla ,nosrep tnereffid a otni denrut dah - ssalc eht ni stneduts eht lla dna
.sdnah sih gnurw labkA
,sretrauq ’srekam dna seitisrevinu dna seimedaca eht was eh ,knalf eht sdrawot
.)etaf nwo rieht sdrawot nellaf evah yeht hcihw ot eerged eht swohs ti
,yaw ym fo tuo teg ton lliw
,gniworht-raeps dna ,yrettop
.niaga maerd eht ni flesmih dnuof ylsuoinomerecnu awniK dna
od nac I ,yaw sihT
.erutaretil rof noissap a htiw yksuh lacisum a ,rettiR yb
”?daed tey ton uoy era woH
etaf emas eht ot elpoep nwo sih tup thgim eh
”reenignE eht dna
”,ffulb a s’taht wonk I ,eeS“  ”!sdrauG !sdrauG
,ytisrevinu lacinhcet eht otni detpecca saw awniK oS
;sniks nwo rieht evas ot snalp tuo yrrac tonnac yeht taht dehsilbatse ydaerla evah eW
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
robal launam ekil meht taert dna
.flesym sedulcni taht dna ,tem reve evah I nosrep trams tsebmud eht era uoy ,labkA“
,dnim sih fo sessecer eht hguorht gnivoM
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
ydob suoicsnocnu sih fo sgnikrow renni eht otni reep ot elba saw awniK taht dnim fo yretsam sih hguorht ylno saw tI
,ytic eht fo ’daeh‘ eht tA
gnitibahni saw eh ydob eht taht
,rehctip eht morf erom tib elttil a gnihsalps ,awniK dias ”,I“
- dnah ym gnidiug enoemos fo tifeneb eht tuohtiw stuh nwo ym edam evah I“ .awniK detroter
moorssalc eht ni kcab llits saw eh taht
.awniK deilper ”,hsuh hO“
”,morf si ti ohw wonk ot tnaw I dna
.did gnik lanrefni eht sa
,pihw a ekil sgnirts eht fo eno dekcarc tI
.daeh sti evoba gnilggaw srae sti ,rellortnoc eht deirc
,deneppah siht keew tsrif ehT
draeh gnol dah awniK woN
.)tuo denrut ti ,gninommus naht redrah hcum taht ton(
.nem dekciw fo srepsihw eht dna seil si esle lla
.ekas ’ssendoog rof ,uoy no sbewboc evah uoY
”.sgninrom eht ni dnetta ot sessalc evah lla ew dna
”,lautir eht fo tniop elohw eht s’taht tuB“
,sevlesmeht erew yeht tub
,rellortnoc eht fo eman eht saw demussa eh tahw rof eman sih tuo deppaws eH
,moor latsyrc a ni flesmih dnuof yletaidemmi dna
”?dnim ym ni gniod uoy era tahw dna“ ,erugif eht dehceercs ”,uoy era ohW“
,gnitnuh syad sih fo tser eht tneps dna
,ti fo yna ees ot tnaem neeb ton dah eh taht gnileef eht dah awniK ,siht lla tuohguorhT
,rellortnoc eht gnidnif nopu dna
”!ecnis reve ylsuolevram ytic eht devres sah ti dna
sa era sreenigne lla ton taht deredisnoc uoy evaH
”!sevlesmeht sgnidliub nwo rieht ngised lliw yeht taht eveileb em evah lliw uoy ,txeN
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.yadot rof deniadro saw taht krow eht od s’tel ,emoC“
,niaga draobklahc a fo tnorf ni tnew reven eh tuB
dias syawla sredle yM
nosaer was taht dnim sih fo kcab eht ta trap llams a saw ereht rof
,oobat gnihcaet redisnoc yeht taht si hcihw
eht erew yehT .emoh rieht edam stna hcihw revo dnuorg eht no tsaeb pmil ,tnaig a erew ti fi sa ytic eritne eht fo erawa emaceb awniK
”.erus rof retteb tol a leef ll’uoy nehT
.sih ton saw taht eciov a htiw ,deksa
.od ot gnihton dah yeht ylneddus taht dezilaer ylkciuq
;pihsecitnerppa evissap tsom eht tub lla od dna ,srebmun ni laed
sgniht taerg rof tnaem s’eh suoivbo s’ti
,pu dnuorg eht morf eloportem siht tliub I
?tsrif tsniaga deltserw eb ot evah ton did taht eb ereht dluoc egdelwonk tahW
od yhW“ .deffocs labkA
;esle lla evoba gnisir elpmet dnarg dna ecalap eht ees dluoc awniK
,mih fo retteb eht teg snoitauqe eseht tel ot ton denimreted ,awniK
”.llif ot ssenlayor ruoy rof slessev sa uoy ot rettam ylno yeht taht noisserpmi eht steg enO
redisnoc ton did gnik dlo eht ,yletanutrofnU
.rellortnoc eht denihw
gnirob os tsuj erew sessalc emos ,yllaeR .peelsa llef eh
. sessenisub rieht dna ecnediser rieht edam snezitic eht erehw sretrauq eht dna sgnidliub
,revo gnillaf dna ekawa gnikrej
!siht rof daeh ruoy evah lliw I“
dehtaerw ,seye nailitper htiw
.noituac elbisnesni siht deleuf taht nwonknu tsav dna egnarts a fo raef ylraelc saw ti ,oN
.swodaem eht gnoma gnikcilorf fo
- ti fo tuo gnisir tsud htiw
- stnemerusaem gnorw eht no gnissap
,nees reve dah nobutaM eht tneduts tsethgirb dna tseb eht saw awniK
,desolc seye sih htiw meht od dluoc eh litnu yldetaeper smelborp ecitcarp eht devlos
dluow sreiziv yM“
.gniwerb evah uoy gniht wen revetahw
,rettiR yb ”reenignE eht dna awniK“ saw sihT
,seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.sebor tew fo elip dna stnemragrednu hguorht-dekaos eht rof t’nerew ti fi
,deneppah siht emit txen ehT
wonk I hcihw ,ni era ew dnim ym si sihT“
srotcurtsni eht sa gnola wollof dluoc eh
”,rehtorb ,nekatsim era uoY“
,retteb on deraf awniK ,revewoh ,keew gniwollof ehT
?taht naht erom yna eb ot deen yeht
;srebmun dna slobmys htiw laed eh did ron
,modgnik ym deniur tsurT“
nommus-nu ot woh tuo gnirugif sruoh wef txen eht tneps awniK dna
,noihsuc tevlev a pota etasnesni dna deggel-ssorc gnitaolf ,retnec eht nI
”?dnim ym ni gniod uoy era tahw dna“
!kool ,taht hguone ssalc eht fo tser eht ot pu thguac dah awniK ,keew driht eht no ,yllaniF
uoy fI .uoy htiw gniklat - !s’esle enoyreve dna
elpoep nobutaM ehT  rettiR yb
,yrrauq eht rof tfel dna
”!oot ti deniur ev’uoy won dna
tip tnaig a dleheb eh
.)god gnitnuh lufhtiaf sih htiw gniyalp fo erew smaerd eht ,emit siht(
,erofeb derolpxe dah eh htap latnem eht koot awniK
.yletaidemmi seiduts wen sih nageb dna
rehtegot emac yeht tuB
.ytiC eht fo tiripS ,won ;nòluT fo gniK tsriF ,labkA ma I“
.flesruoy ti od dluoc uoy fi boj a etageled reven ot
gniraperp erew srotcurtsni eht snoitauqe dna smargaid eht taht decuded noos eH
,noitisop lager tsomla na ni thgirpu
- thgil wolley ni dednuorrus
.lairetam eht gnidnatsrednu sdrawot krow dna
yb dah I snalp tuo-dial ylenif eht lla hctob
,nugeb evah dluow liat eht erehw ,nwod rehtruf dna
awniK“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
dluow dna ,yad eht fo sseniraew eht yb nekatrevo ylneddus flesmih dnif dluow eh
pu doots ,awniK gnidulcni ,ssalc eritne eht ,eno sA
- emoceb setamssalc sih nees dah awniK nosrep eht yltcaxe
smaerd sseltser otni llaf
,tnorf ot kcab sgnidaer eht hguorht tnew
.dnuora rehctip eht gnihsols ,awniK dias
- !smelborp ylsaem wef a evlos ot elbanu nobutaM eht fo edirp eht ,enigami
.sredluob nevrac taerg gnitsioh syellup emos sa llew sa
.gnimrof-margaid dna
.ytic eritne eht gnikoolrevo taruggiz a pota
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.erugif eht delbmurg ”,enif ,eniF“  ”.gnivael
,dekri ylsuoires woN
,taht wonk ot awniK deifirret ti dna
.eye s’dnim sih gnisu margaid gninommus eht ’tniap‘ ot dedeecorp
.dluohs ti sa gnideecorp si noitcurtsnoc taht erus ekam dna seidob ruoy revo ekat I“
.meht fo strap tnereffid eht lla dootsrednu eh litnu strahc dna smargaid eht trapa koot dna
,stnemhserfer fo lluf elbat a morf edisa gnihton gniees dna dnuora gnikool ,awniK
.sdnim s’elpoep fo kcab eht ta evil taht stirips eht ot klat ot woh wenk neve eH
,seirutnec ynam ,ynam revo tiperced dna liarf emoceb dah
.deeh on ti diap eh tub ,egdelwonk eslaf tsniaga sredle eht fo snoitacerped eht
- dias ebirt eht fo elpoep eht tahw s’taht dna
,skeew yb kcab noitcurtsnoc tes ev’uoy ,noitartnecnoc ym gnitpurretni yB“
.sdliug gnireenigne demeetse ro seitisrevinu taerg rieht ot noissimda kees dluoc eh fi ees ot
,dnuora dellor sessalc lausu eht emit txen ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
esproc nifle eht dna flesmih htob
.tuo ro ni semoc ydobon tub ,ti tae uoy ,ni doof eht nommus uoY
.gnivael ton m’I ;tnaw uoy fi yad elohw eht siht ta peek nac eW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
,ydob sih fo lortnoc nekat yledur os dah ohw nosrep suoiretsym eht ta kcab teg ot devloser eh
.mrof lairetam ot awniK dna flesmih gninruter erofeb ,daeh s’awniK ni eciov s’labkA demoob
etamtaes sih ”?awniK ,thgir lla uoy erA“
nòluT taht deneppah os tI
”!ecaep ni noitcurtsnoc ym od ot em evael dna dnim ym fo tuo
?sreiziv ruoy sa dedaeh-enob