,smra s’rehtona ni ro
.ria eht niats ylgnimlehwrevo taht selbide gnorts ylitsum htiw deriap era saet eht dna srueuqil yb dekips era seeffoc ehT
,gnivom era kcap eht ni senob ehT
eeffoc rehtona tnaw I
”.ti etaicerppa t’ndid I
.slobmys lasrevinu htiw sngis railimaf dna ocitrop nepo na no rood nepo rehtona htiw
.ekil-esuom ,kaeuqs I
ekoms gnignah wol a
,spil yhtoot reh no der eht tsniaga krats tniap etihw
,tirips a sah gnihtyreve ereH“
.slatsedep rewolfnroc eruza rieht no rodnelps tnargarf htiw
serutaerc fo sdeen eht ta tnemesuma htiw rednow I dna
.pots yawbus a ro
nwonk yllasrevinu elur a si siht
ytsum gnihtemos fo ecnaraeppa dega eht sah pohs ehT
ecarg dehctam fo
.trofmoc fo ecalp ym
.kcab dna ekac delewejeb-esor eht ot kcab gnicnalg
ylgnivol dna ylgnignol gnikool
.ton ro lufetarg eb dluohs I fi erus ton m’I tub ,eltsirb d’I
,ylevitcelloc doow dna ssarb dna selit dna swodniw dna sllaw eht ot ,neht dna
.nekopsnu erehwyreve dna
snortap rehto s’éfac sirpyK llA
,ereh ti evael uoy erehw si gnihtyrevE“
rab eht ta tnip a kcab gnikconk regdab A
.gnirutparne saw txen emac tahw fo gninnigeb eht sa ,tnavelerri saw dne ehT
?uoy evol taht sriahc dna selbat dna sllaw ruof htiw od uoy od tahw oS“  .timmaD
.yaw emos ni em fo strap elbarapesni lla era esehT
.yawa raet tsal reh seird dna
hcra der 'sirpyK ta pots ew sa
.nwod ecalp siht gnittup em raeh t’ndid yeht dalg m’I kniht I
.lanosrep eb ot sdeen ti tuoba gnihtoN
ecalp yna evol nac eno taht
.thgis fo tuo dna
,uoy ot dehcatta si éfac ehT
eeffoc fo spis ro ekac enieledam fo spid
luos yrev s’pohs eeffoc eht ekil
.sriahc dekcab-rekciw dna
.mih ekil eno dnif ll’uoy ,flesruoy esol uoy reverehW“
,ecalp siht fo ton dna em fo trap a si daer I tahw fI ?ton yhw lleW
.avaJ dna niG s’legnA
.flesym naelc ot deen I ezilaer dna
,seidob lufreehc yb dellif em dnuora lla sriahc demraw ,deipucco ni tsuj ton
.em fo noisnetxe na si siht ebyam os
,erehwyna og nac I won wonk I
.su nesohc s’taht ereh ecalp eno evah lla t’nod eW“  .syas etoyoc eht
.peels ot evah t’nod I
elggurts ot em thguorb sniap dna syoj erehw
,yromem morf tpews si hcum os taht nosaer taht rof s’ti dna ereh enoyna erutrot t’ndluohs stbuoD
su nihtiw sworg ,su sllif
”.kcab uoy evol nac ti
,ecalp siht ni niaga sgniraeb ym teg nac I
”.esaelp ,sliateD .repeed oG
.morf trapa ro ot esolc erew ew sgniht ro elpoep eht htiw ecaep ta er’ew yhw
.sduolc rednu nedrag esor a ksud knip eht
.diap era ytilatrom ot seud yM
;derob nettog ev’I
.tnetnoc ,trapa ,rehtegot
oga tnemom a litnu pu taht ecaps eht ni em morf elbat llams ym ssorca stis ehs sa
.ksud tcefrep a rednu selbboc eht gniffucs seohs ym
”.demees ti os rO“  .syas etoyoc eht ”,enola syawlA“
.ereht ni gnitaolf gnihtemos fo tnemgarf llams a ees dna
yrd ot niats krad eht gnilliw
.ereh thgir ediser lliw yoj ym tub
.nwod tes eb ot gnihtemos llits tub
,etalp eht no eikooc eripme na si erehT
,pot niatnuom a evol dluoc uoY
”?elbatrofmoc uoy sekam tahw dnA“
.ti wonk I ;ma I sa laer sa era yehT
,deraeppa sah ekac etihw eroM
,secalp rehto fo ytivarg eht ekiL
,snoitalupinam ruoy morf yawa teg t’nac I kniht dna enil a em deeF .etoyoc diputS
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.noitceffa ruoy yllaicepse
;no tsaef ydaerla seye ym tahw trapa skcip eson enilef etaciled yM
,selkcah yM .retskcirt eht
,yppah eb ot eb ot deen I revetahW
”.su esoohc t’nod secalP“
.erehwyna taht evah nac uoY“
.deneteews-revo tib a
.ytpme tiaw gum dna sserp ehT
tnemhsinelper otni kcab sevlesmeht ekab sdoog debrutsid eht elihw eht llA
”,ti tcepxe tsael uoy erehw ssenippaH“
,lufthgiled tsom eht si
”?uoy lliw ,em htiw kcab klaW .duolC s’tI“
em hguorht redduhs a gnidnes swap ym no htmraw fo kcohs eht
reh diova ot ediced uoy fi neve uoy sevol sirpyK“
,nevaeh fo erafhguoroht eht klaw I
,nevaeh ni ehcèrc ynit ym dnuof emas yrev eht dna
.roolf dna elbat eht morf pu flesti snaelc llips ehT .knilb I
.tius depirtsnip ym evoba detpoda ev’I relwob eht tlit I dna
dirul ylthgils sraeppa thgis larehpirep ym ni rocéd ehT
.eeffoc ym pis dna koob ym emuser
si ekac detsorf etihw ehT
.iras reh gnitsujda
.sserP lesaeW dna
,sselesnes si aedi elohw eht tuB
,htap nedrag a gnola dekcip ev’I egasroc calil a ta gnikop
,sessap thgiN .gnihctiwt liat
.em sesahc noitceffa ydeen fo edahs errazib oN
.reh etah I ediced I
ni knurd dlrow ym fo sliated eht
.efil yna fo tnemele gnisufnoc tsom eht si evoL
.saw taht reverehw
.ydaer ta sserp dna koob
,su fo lareves era ereht dna
,flesti htiw dehsinifnu
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.edutilos emoclew fo
.esiwrehto evil t’ndluoc eW
,amsaim a emoceb evah
a noitibihorp gnirud tes rorroh dnalgnag ogacihC a
,tnemyojne ym rof ereh ti tup dna
,dekan si emit siht elicimod yduolc eht ot nruter yM
,reporp éfac eht ni kcab er’ew ,tnemom a nI
.flesym yb ti yojne ot tnaw I“
”.esidarap yojne ot gnihtyreve dnatsrednu ot evah t’nod uoY“
.wodahs on stsac ehs hguoht neve
,ereht llits si ytniatrecnu eht tuB
kcab sih ot dexiffa xa-elttab a sah em ot kcab sih htiw eno ehT
yllufecarg sesir etoyoc ehT
.enif tsuj s’taht tub ,em wonk t’nseod ecalp sihT
;si aedi elohw eht ytitnedi ym fo noitisopmi drusba na tahW
,era ylirassecen nevaeh ni srood lla sa
.snirg etoyoc eht ”,evol uoy tuB“
.lla su rof esidarap ni ecalp a setaerc dna
.teiuq fo mlaer llams ruo otni tfird srenroc lla morf rethgual dna noitarbelec suoretsiob stel etoyoc ehT ”?uoy era ohW“
.sdus sehsols dna skaerb eno taht hguone drah rehtegot stnip rieht mals dna
.ekac detsurcne-esor eht ot kcab kniht I
.ortni eht ,elbmaerp eht
recuas a no puc deldnah-gnir A
.ecips dna htmraw naccoroM fo egnalem ylevil a si eeffoc ehT
.luos rehtona fo rrennam eht ni
.si tahw sees ohw enoemos tsuj m’I
.suoivbo eht tuo gnitniop hguoht sa
.seod syawla tI .ereh uoy speek evoL .ereh uoy thguorb evoL
.emac I erofeb saw I tac eht rebmemer t’nod I
.ereh emit ym lla ni ecno gnar reven sah dna dennam-nu stser
ecaf ot ecaf emoc dna
.sdrawni degnih yllanrete
skoob ni saw ti fo kcal ro ssenippah ym
snekcals msaisuhtne reh dna
”.edutilos dna trofmoC
.edisbus neht dna borht gnits eht leef dna
.noitidart morf kaerb tub
.evitpecer dna ediw srae
,si ecalp siht em fo trap a hcum woh egdelwonkca ot
,onomik kcalb a ni emit siht
.ti yas uoy draeh ev’I
.daeh ym kcoc dna elzzum etihw detniap taht no eson kcalb eht revo kool I
.ytimixorp sti ta ytniatrecnu ron
.dnuorg delbboc ot
won desuma erom neve si etoyoc ehT
,nihplod a ,noil a ,tibbar A
.su setelpmoc ,su serahs ohw enoemos
.nwod ecaf nepo koob
,flesym taes I sa emit emos rof em ta sezag ehS
.niaga reh ees reven dna
”.stnaw yllaer traeh rieht tahw
”,eman ruoy ksa t’ndid I“
,redluohs sih revo eralg a em sevig
.egap nepo eht no delbbub llits
,segap eseht ni dniheb tfel evah tsum I dlrow eht fo rednimer a hcuS
.os gniod rof dah I nosaer tahw ro
.tniop elohw eht si
.esir I sa ezilaer I
.gniyas m’I tahw tpecca ot gnimoc hguoht sa
,imak ti dellac napaJ dellac ecalp A
sa lanrete edam ,syoj gniteelf tsom eht rof
”,em dewollof uoy fi ksa ot gniog saw I“
noitcelfer gnissap ym sa senap wodniw eht no remmihs tew eht gnidiova ,no evom I
”.tnatropmi ton s’tI .erofeb morf em ekil enoemos swonk enoyrevE“
,sdileye desolc dniheb taeper I
.snoitalutargnoc fo rennam eht ni syas etoyoc eht
.kcen ym elkcit separd nward ehT
,sraeppa éfac sirpyK fo latrop der eht sa dna
,gniwonk fo tfig eht nevig si enoyreve ,tac ,dnatsrednU
,ereh taht si ecnereffid ylno ehT
,setib wef a ylno seviecer tnassiorc ehT
.doow ro hself fo
,tsael ta em nees sah s'legnA
,nevaeh ni snoitcartsid on era erehT
sirpyK morf thgilf ym gnirud fo kcart tsol d’I koob eht taht ees dna kcehc I
,ysaenu gnileef evael dna
pu kool I yllanif neht
,ecno tsuj fi neve
niaga eeffoc ym pis I
.sserd reppalf a dna ehcolc eulb a ni desserd ,niaga ereht si etoyoc ehT
.elihwa yats dna pu thgil llew sa yaM“
.seye esiw reh gninil kcalb
sseltops ylesrevnoc tub ,ni devil dna
.wap reh ni detsefinam sah taht ssalg looc a morf spis neht
.etteragic a tuohtiw htuom a morf gnilruc ekoms luof
spots etoyoc ehT  ”…enoemos ton fi
sluos etarapes tub derdnik tsgnoma
.ereh reh rednop t’now I .oN —I elihw
.thgis fo tuo stser dna swols neht
,won ma I tahw dnA
,esoppus I ,dluow os od oT
,em dnuora ecneserp fo gnilkcarc emos yb wena pu nward m’I erofeb koob ym ni daeha hpargarap rehtona ylerab m’I  .won I nac roN
.koorb a sa lacisum si em dnuora klat dna rethguaL
elit dehsilop eht no kcilc swalc reH
.daeha esnes suordnow yreve elpmas taht sreksihw eht ro
,maet s’avaj fo tfaw eht revo rehtona eno drager ereh ni slammam rehto ehT
,eb ot desoppus si esidarap tahw si sihT
,em revo rewop yna sdloh taht ecalp a morf evol detiuqer-sim oN
?won em seugalp tahw oS
.eil a lla si ti spahreP
,esoper dna yoj ni sluos rehto fo gnorht eht otni
,em no setod pohs eeffoc gnivol yM
,syaw tnereffid ni won ni tsixe ew dlrow eht wonk ot emac lla eW
.nevaeh ni noitasnes siht leef ton dluohs enO
elttes emit fo sdnas eht leef dna
,esirprus a si siht fo hcuM
,tser ot eldarc morf decnad I
,daer I sa tsrif ta stsefinam gnihtoN .koob ym gnidaer
,mra ym rednu llits si
yltsenoh rewsna I
edutilos ym rovas I
,rorrim eht ni ezag I
,der fo semarf ereht dna ereh dna
.slepal ym nwod htooms ot em segru taht pets ym ni pans a dna puenil on dna
tac sihT .erised ew
.elims a htiw sedihc etoyoc eht
gum etihw-enob eht epacse spord on os erac htiw ruop
.yaw elohw eht ria eht ni liat ym evah enieffac fo stsohg ehT
,ylticat rehtar ,syas rood eht evoba ngis ehT
.ma I woh tsuj s’tI
,koob deird eht ta nwod erats I
.tnatropmi gnihtemos gnissim m’I hguoht sa ,ria eht ni ytirailucep fo esnes a si erehT
nevaeh siht fo tekcol s’traeh tsav eht sdnuorrus taht niks llehsgge eulb eht ot hguorht
.pohs eeffoc ym fo sliated eht no gnikniht ,duolc ym ni yal I dna yad a neht
,ytrap nedrag potfoor a ta
.gnikaos a erised dluow I yhw fo kniht t’nac I
,edutilos debircsorp-fles ym rof snosaer eht tuo kees reven ll’I
,swodniw reh hguorht nus eht fo htmraw gnisaecnu eht
”.gniklaw peeK .ereh neve ,seY
.em gnidihc ro tnemeerga ni rehtie era semihc ehT
”,ecalp siht evol I“
lwoy a htiw tnerrot eht morf kcab wap ym ward I
.dnah ynob sih ni kcap eht ot sllaf ezag ym sa hctiwt sreksihw yM ”.regnol ebyaM
,ytivarg a sah efiL
,tnemom siht ni sehtolc deen I rof ,sehtolc yM
;rebmemer I neht tuB  .ereh reven dna
.stonk sseldeen ni flesym gniyt
,railimafnu yllohw si ereh ni ebiv ehT
etalp ym no yranoitcefnoc llehs-aes eht
,eeffoc eht dellips I erehw elbat eht no llits si koob yM
.yawa em desahc taht drocsid eht dewos ehS
?enod si tahW“ ”.enod si ti woN
.tsuorP ym daer I ;tis I
.morf emac I erehw saw I esoppus I sa ,ma I
.ti ton saw hcus
”,wonk ot evah t’nod uoY“
.enola su dna su ot evol sti nevig sah éfac sirpyK gnimussa hcae
”?su ekil elpoep neewteb detnarg ylno si evol etanoitceffa eurt taht eveileb uoy oS  .ohW“
sepacsdnal larotsap fo shcytpyrt dna repapllaW
.tneserp reve dna
,em ot kcab snrut ehs sA
.yliratnemom ylno tub
.enoyreve rof tuo devrac nevaeh fo ecils a s’erehT
.teerts siht nwod dna pu lla snocaeb gninokceb etaerc noen dna muidos fo skcil dna
.em ot neila emoceb sah taht noitanretsnoc gnileef
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.did reven uoY .em wonk t’nod uoY“
.esnes nac uoy taht htmraw a
.tac siht deugalp reven ssenilenoL
.ssenismulc ym gniciton serutaerc suocuar rehto eht fo enon
.ycnega lanoitome na ,ecrof a
,noitpecrep sretla taht sucof ni egnahc thgils a tsuj htiw dna
.der ni ettesor gnitsorf ynit a htiw emit siht
.kcab gnikool erofeb gurhs a htiw ezag ym gniwollof ,syas etoyoc eht
,gniffins ,dekoorc snroh
,edistuo eht fo soahc yssem eht swollof taht redro eht
”.ecaps etaminani na ,ecalp a ,pohs eeffoc a si sirpyK“
.gum gnillif-reve ym gniknird dna skoob ym gnidaeR
,srenroc ytpme eht ni tub
.evael I nehT .enola yats I
meht ssorca selppir
.egde s’gidnihs eht ta
.dnuorgyalp sseldne s’esidarap ni gnidliub rehtona tsuj
.daerd yduolc ekil
,rood nepo eht ot pu eldis I
.ainnellim ro sruoh enog saw I fi rebmemer t’nac I  .ni em gnimoclew
,steerts eht rednaw I
.won daer ot derit oot tub nepo koob
,ssenteews ni demufrep ,nehT
.semulov enitsirp ,etarapes ynam os sah yrots eht lufknaht ma I
.spord fo olah sti dna llips eht brosba
esrevinu eht fo elttil dnamed I
selbat derevoc-htolc eht fo ecnagele elpmis eht evol I
,eerga ot em rof stiaw ehs sa sgaw liat s’etoyoc ehT
srehto ot siht daerps sah etoyoc eht spahreP
,srorrim eht ot esolc ,rood eht ot kcab del m’I sa nworf I
,kcab si etoyoc eht yad txeN
.meht rof tiaw nevaeh fo sevalcne revetahw
dna setihw-ffo esehT
,srorrim gnirettalf fo ruolrap a
.dniw tlefnu na ni gnidniw
”.pohs eeffoc a evol t’nod I ?dab taht sI
,eeffoc eht evol I
yretra s’nevaeh nwod espiart elpmis a htiw nevorp ev’I
.noitanevujer dna esoper fo ecaps siht
,tnorf ym revo lla eeffoc fo spord
.sirpyK ta eeffoc eht ssim I dna
.yaw emos ni ,enoemos ton fi ,gnihtemos evol lla ew tuB
,ti ekat dna taes a dnif I
rettib llits s’tI .pis a ekat
selbboc eht skcilc kcits gniklaw yM
,taht yas ot doog sleef tI  ”.uoy evol I“
”,sdroffa edutilos modeerf eht ekil I“
.peew ylbaborp dluow I
.tcefrep si ruop eht dna sdnecsed sserp ehT
.taht ekil tsuj ,won yrd ma flesym I tuB
.noitcerid yreve ni
yletanoitceffa gnittap
.elihw a sekat ti ebyaM
.enihs nosmirc sti senihs hcihw
.stluser eht snworc htorf fo daeh lemarac A .sdnecsed
.pis a laets I nehw rettib dna
.tcepsus emoceb sah ti tub ,stiawa noitop krad eht dna yrd si taorht yM
,pohs eeffoc eht otni yaw eht no etoyoc dediarb a ssap I .enola si
?sehtolc eseht raew I diD
em teseb evah dluoc taht seillof eht ot sa gninraw a hcus
.uoy dlot I“ ”?sesirprus tahW“
etatidem ot teg I yltsom tub
,nworf ot gnileef egnarts a s’tI
,evac detniap a ,esuoh eivom A
.noisufnoc ni gnilleviws srae ,rettum I
,yas I ”,wonk t’nod I“
.enim tsuj eb ot ti rof ecaps eht erahs srehto ynam ooT
flesti hcihw retsiger hsac tnatsid eht evoba gnis semihC
nwog nitas a ot yaw nevig sah iras reH
.rettam t’nseod ti ,dias duolC sA
.ylsuoivbo ,esnepxe ym ta nuf gnivah s’ehS
.rehtona retfa cipot gnigagne eno dnuor dniw
.tnaw I tahw s’tahT
dias etoyoc eht ”,sruoy dnuof uoY
,slenap doow dna sgnittif ssarb
detfis seiromem ruo
.ralucitrap ni enoyna ro ,snortap rehto eht
.em swonk éfac sirpyK llew woH
,tuo selffuhs taog a dna
?syerg evitatidem
”.yawyna emit eht fo tsom ,lleW“
.traeh ruoy dnuof tI
.seriuqer ti lla s’tahT
.eugnot gnol reh skcilc ehs dna
.ylbatrofmoc daer ot hguone tsuj neht
.taht lla rof rekaew wohemos si ti
.kcilc a htiw latrop eht slaes dna
”,fo gnikaeps er’uoy tahw wonk t’nod I"
,em fo tnorf ni koob eht ot noitnetta gniyap elbuort gnivah m’I
.koob ym ot txen dniheb ti evael I
.niaga ecno ecaep tcefrep ni em sdnif rebmulS
llats eht fo krad eht otni skcab erugif deggar eht sa yawa em sdael
.elbatrofmoc er’ew erehw secalp era erehT“
.hcamots ym ni stcesni erew stbuod fi rednow ylpeed reven
.snoisluper dna serised 'srehto fo snoitanihcam eht otni derettacs tcejbus tsol sti htiw ,koob ym no etartnecnoc ot drah s’tI
.esiw eht naht tuoba daer ot gnitseretni erom hcum os era slooF
.deyonna naht gniytip erom
.nevaeh fo trap llams a ni m’I   floW-pilS yb
,floW-pilS yb 8 emuloV raoR  ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw hcihw ,”ssiK ’sirpyK“
.seiceps yreve fo
.gnimoctrohs ro niap emos llacer
,snoitcerid tnereffid morf em gnillup era sgnileef tnereffiD ”?uoy era ohW“
nosaer fo ecnesba eht yleman
,evael I sa ekaw ym ni gnirrits dloc tcnitsid a s’erehT
.taes detivninu na sekat
.em rof edam t’nsaw tI
rettahc gnidnuorrus fo stnerruc ehT
.eeffoc a ees dna
”.od I neve erofeb stnaw doom ym tahw swonk syawla ecalp eht yaw eht
.tib eno ti ekil I yaw eht morf delooc t’nsah hcihw
,ti tnaw I fi em sdnif rebmulS
”.suoires eb t’nac uoY“
.ecneserp ruoy htiw evol taht etammusnoc uoY“
,htaerb detab htiw tnemom eht yaled I
.drawpu maerc eht rits dna
,diuqil ni debbad neeb sah koob ym nevE
.erehw ksa ot gnideen ton ,don I
.niaga dna niaga ereh uoy thguorb evoL
.ni em ecitne ecnedaced tresed ,yegnops dna naeb eeffoc dnuorg fo ecnargarf nrow-llew eht
.hcum taht rebmemer I .enola tub
.erised fo tselpmis ym daer dna
.pohs eht ot yas I
.retne I hcihw hguorht
,ogol defael-revlis sirpyK eht htiw
,htoob ym ni ereht tis I .nmad lleW
spil ym sehcuot ssik naccoroM a nehT
,hguorht sessap ehs sa emarf rood der eht no wap reh stup ehS
,noivilbo morf efas
.meht ot nruter ot redro gnilliw
”.flesruoy edistuo…“
.etib rettib-ffo ot
.tnatculer tub ,tnelis si gnitrap s’duolC
,erofeb dlrow eht fo semilc redloc eht ni htroN raf elihw
”.gnihton detpecca ev’I
s'ti ebyam ,cinot dna nig s’ti ebyaM
.koob ym fo egap delknirw eht ta nwod ylgnignol ecnalg dna
gnorht eht fo tuo enim gnikcip
.eno rehtona tnaw t’nod uoy nehw yllaicepsE
.sllaw esoht ni pis yreve dna
,mra ym rednu si koob yM
puc ym otni kool I
.eno siht erofeb yrutnec
.dneirf a fo redluohs eht no hguoht sa
”?uoy debrutsid evol fo noisseforp eht tuoba tahW
”?ereht fo daetsni ereh uoy era yhw oS
wodniw detsorf a gnillif sekac ees I dna ,gnici ragus dna
.spil ym sehsurb gnihtemos dna
.emoclew t’nera taht enon ,llew
ecalp elohw siht etaemrep taht stnecs kciht ehT
,naf detalp-ssarb ,gninrut wols eht tsap gniliec deoccuts eht ta pu kool I
.nortap rehto yna naht erom
,egamad retaw morf delppir dna yvaw segap
koob ym esolc I
,pat eht rednu retaw nur I
,taog eht ta ezag wolley reh sworran etoyoc ehT
.suouconni dna nepo tsom
,bup legnA eht ni gnitagergnoc sluos fo dworc eht snacs dna yawa snrut ehS
.neppah ti tel tsuJ“
,ynobe eseht otno
tnemhserfer gnilgnit fo sonirtuen
,niaga sucoF .su fo lla rof
sgum dna stopaet eht gnoma dna detalosi tub
.em fo gnihton sdnamed ti dna
.thgilsag gnihctac iras nedlog reh no eergilif eht
”?enoyna ot deirram gnieb enigami uoy naC“
.eergilif fael-dlog hguor ni maets ffo stel
,gnihtemos rof evol dnif uoy
,gninraey dna ,noisufnoc si evoL“
.sruof lla no depol evah dluoc I ro deklaw evah dluoc I
.gnivah naht suordnow ssel on si gnirovas esuaceb siht od I tub deen on s’ereht
,gnimoorg ekil leef I revenehw dekan ylehtil m’I
nwod sserp eht tes I sa sesir maetS
.ezag ym teem t’nseod ehS
drazil a yb enrob ssalg-initram a htiw gnola ,srellabhgih dna stnip reeb cidarops ees I
.lla ta koob ym no sucof ot elbanu ma I ,yad txen ehT
ragus gnici fo tnilg eht yB
.sirpyK dna uoY .deirram era uoY
.pu esrevinu eht gnidda sucaba na ekil tsirw reh ot rehto hcae esahc stelecarb eht dna
.yaw a hcus ni evirht ot noitceliderp egnarts a hcuS
,kciht si eletneilc ehT
.su fo tser eht ekil tsuJ“
htiw eye s’dnim ym erofeb hsalf yllanoisacco taht secaf ehT
.elpoep ynam os fo sloof gnikam
.noitasnes htiw sedaf taht
.sesir etoyoc ehT ”.og ot tog ev’I
.tnecs sti fo tib a rehtag ot ti gnola knalf worran ym bur dna
.delpmas reve ev’I kniht I yoj yragus yraniluc fo ecils yria
,gnihton yb dnuob era ew esidarap nI
.gnikrow t’nsi eeffoc ehT
.thgir leef t’nseod gnihtemos tub ,sesnes ym elgnit taht setib wef a ekat I
.ralucitrap ni ydobon ksa I
,setoyoc fo snoitisopsid retskcirt eht fo esruoc fo wonk I
.srehto ni sevlesmeht rof noitceffa dnif ot
,nosaer a rof ecalp taht depacse I
lioc latrom eht ni em ot tsom derettam taht gniht eno eht ekat ylbissop dluow esle tahW
,detiuqernu ti sevael etaf nehw neve taht dnik eht fo evol a dna
.ti dnib nac taht evol on fo
.ecnacifingisni ot dengisnoc
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,floW-pilS yb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.nihtiw peed ecnabrutsid fo gnileef taht
,neht saw I erus m’I sa
.roprot etaipo na ni yawa spis ohw
dimaryp engapmahc a morf ylbbub teews fo pis a ni
ssenteews dekab morf evom nac I
yellaV tibbaR ,tenalpruF
.dedisbus fi tneserp llits esaenu fo esnes ym
em dniheb desiar liat eht sa fles fo esnes ym fo trap sa
.senob-regnif deffuts-occabot ekil skool tahw fo kcap nepo na pu sdloh dna sezeehw eh
.dnim on su gniyap
roloc emas eht si ruf yM
”.edutilos ehT .teiuq ehT“
.flesym tcelloc ot emit emos sekat ti os ,yhw wonk etiuq t’nod I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.neesnu sdnah suortxed yb no detod
.nettogrof tub lla dlrow a ni erofeb semit sseltnuoc dah ehs sa
.mraerof ym sezeeuqs dna
wol era sthgil s’nevaeh nehw tisiv ohw sluos lanrutcon era ereht enigami dluow I
nevaeh nI .rehtona neht
.rood eht ot edilg ot snigeb dna
,em htiw pu steg ehs sa syas ehs ”,t’ndid uoy oN“
”?gniog uoy era erehW“
.tuo deppets ev’I
.ssalg reh nwod stes dna
”.skcirt rof eno reven saw I .skcirt oN
.gniknihtnu ,t’nod I oS
mosob yna fo tnemllecrosne eht yb nwod deit eb reven lliw I taht
,ecnatniauqca ro ylimaf fo egdelwonk ot kcab evloser reven lliw
.yaw taht ni ton ,kcab sirpyK evol ot evah t’nod uoY“
.dessap sah yad rehtona dna
.nworf I  ”?ereh erofeB“
.lla ta yaw taht evol fo thguoht reven I“
?spil ym ta bad I taht nikpan eht no emufrep yragus ereht sI  ”.uoy evol I“
”ssiK ’sirpyK“:yojne esaelP
nevaeh fo erafhguoroht-ssorc rehtona fo dworc eht otni sedaf etoyoc ehT
.eson ym elknirw I
.ereh rehto yna naht erom ,ecalp taht ot dehcatta er’uoY  ?emag tahW“
”,ydobyreve rof emas eht t’nsi allahlaV“
,egap eht no sdrow eht yb dednocsba si dnim yM
”.em ot tnatropmi si ecalp sihT
.no ekohc ot taorht deltrats tsom eht rof t’nsi nevaeh ni aisorbma enieffac tseteews eht tub ,rettups dluoc I
.elzzum ym fo edisrednu eht no delknirps dna pal ym ssorca daerps
emarf rood der eht hguorht nruter I nehw ereh eb lliw tI .nwod ti tes dna
,flesym ot nekops sdrow on
.taht ot yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I
.ereh ti evael uoy erehw si gnihtyrevE .selit yrovi
erom ecno ehca ll’ehS
.ti tuoba kniht uoy nehw nuf eht fo trap s’taht dna
?ti erahs ohw srehto ereht era rO
.eeffoc ym sa tnargarf dna yegnops
.emoh m’I hguone nooS
.imak sti dnuof uoY“
tsuj si ereh niar looc a nevE
.gnol os rof em dedule sah tcatnoc tceriD
.eno dah ron riahc on dedeen
,elbatrofmocnu dna eeffoc htiw gnippird llits ma I
wodniw 'sirpyK dnoyeb rednuht fo yballul eht si ti netfo tsoM
.snoitseuq ym dna eeffoc ym htiw tfel ma I
emarf rood der emas eht hguorht sevael dna
enoyreve dna gnihtyreve ,ereH“
,snoihsuc hsulp eht tsniaga ni elttes I
,lanrutcon ylerar os ma I taht egnarts oS
,eeffoc ym otni nworf I .ffo si ehs dnA
.sehsinelper eeffoC
,em rof stiaw ecaps yM
”.eno yrram ot hguone pohs eeffoc a evol t’nac I“ ”.hguone saw tahT
”.tsegnorts sti erehw si nruter sti fo noitatcepxe on htiw ti gniviG
,erutaerc yratilos A
noitceffa dna ytisoiruc htiw
.tnemom a rof ssalg reh otni serats ehS
,dne no sredluohs ym no ruf eht sdnats taht
seye dnik htiw em sessap ehs sa
.riahc reh ni stfihs etoyoc ehT
ekoms occabot detsaot dna zzaJ
.yadretsey rebmemer I nehw hgual I dna
.mohtaf ylbatrofmoc nac I naht erom sliatne ylneddus gniretnE
?rotisiv yratilos eht ,em ot evol sti nevig sah pohs eht yhw taht sI
”ssiK ’ssirpyK“ saw sihT
.erutsiom fo stops eht rednu pu gnilbbub egap eht
sdnamruog yb delpmas sgnireffo citoxe sseltnuoc
,sllems railimafnu llems
,enim psarg swap s’etoyoc ehT
.ecno esle erehwemos saw I .emit paN
”.dnuora evom emoS
”?thgir ,gnihtyreve wonk ydaerla uoy erehw dlrow a otno evom ot tnaw uoy dluow yhw naem I
?yned ot s’tahW .sirpyK did oS
.derised sa dna tnesnoc htiw si
,em htiw semoc etoyoc eht dna elbat eht ot nruter I
,ytinrete ni mlac fo sisao siht
”.ecalp siht evol I“
.em ot gniklat si etoyoc eht ezilaer I
”.ti t’nsi siht wonk I tub ,si evol tahw wonk t’nod I“
.gnorts stfaw eeffoc yM
.ecaps otni ffo serats dna mets dereuqcal a hguorht etteragic reh sekoms ehS
,sluos nortap raluger tnetnoc fo aes eht ssorca
.elgnuj dliw fo kcil hsul a
.thgin ta ylraelc daer t’nac I
.ydaer era yeht ,tis I nehW
egde tnatsid s’nevaeh gnola ksud fo sespmilg ro
.spuorg regral ni detcelloc ro
,tnemom ym ni thgirb
.dekan ylraen si dna
wap reh fo htmraw eht etaicerppa I ,won dna ereH
,yletarapes dna ylevitcelloc snoitaroced dna sgnihsinruf 'sirpyK fo lla yduts dna pu kool I
.ecalp siht evol I  .no sessap dna
koob ym ni egap txen eht hsinif I
.rettam t’nseod tI
norpa srenwo pohs eeffoc degdums a ni
shgual etoyoc ehT
,ecaeP dna raW s’yotsloT ot deneppah siht daH
sserp hcnerF ym ot txen em rof gnitiaw ekac ehT
.daetsni gnivrennu dnif I ecneitap a htiw selims tub ,llet nac I
.sllips eeffoc yM .ekil I yaw a ni
,htaerb a sekat dna spots ehS
traeh ylevil reh fo sseniddig eht leef dna
”.snoitpo wef a etiuq s’erehT .wodaem a ni llor rO .sdraillib yalp oT“
,retlif demmir-lioc eht
,sesirprus llits era erehT“ .shgual ehs
.ereh od syawla yeht sa
.gniht a hcus wolla ot esidarap rof esnes on sekam tI
,sserP floWafoS htiw dnuof eb nac nac noitcif trohs siH
.ylmulg yas I  ”,loof a m’I“
,kcab yrruh I yad txeN
leef I .ekac erom sti ees nac I
,éfac ym fo egrahc cirtcele eht leef I sa
”.enola uoy evael lliw I“ ”?tahW“
,eno siht erofeb dlrow eht fo gof eht ecreip ylluf reven ll’I
,rood der eht hguorht evael I nehW .yrgnuh ton m’I
mets gum eht no pirg ym esol I spil ym ot yaw sti nO
.egap eht no ecalp ym tsol gnivah ,tnemom a tegdif I
.ksa t’nod I .retaw
trap llams a si sihT
ecnaifed ni smra ym dlof I
thgil sseldne eht ni tuO
.dedraugnu yal traeh ym dah
woble ym dnuor sparw wap A
?rebmemer t’nod I taht doog ti sI
.yaw emos ni did lla ew sa
.etisiuqxe si eeffoc ehT
koob ym fo segap delppir eht elfir I dna
,erofeb emac tahw fo trap tnatropmi na neeb evah tsum sihT
.ma I lla ot nosaert si aedi yrev ehT
,esidarap fo ymehcla egnarts taht ni em fo trap a
,hturt flah a gniees ma I .neht em tsuJ
.yawa raet a epiw ot reh rof spots gnitegdif reh
htrae deklaw-edis s’nevaeh ot kcab pael I nooS
snepo llats a sa teef ym ffo em sekat gnab A
”?erofeb ecalp a devol reven uoy evaH“
.t’nac I tub ,hgual dluoc I
.egasroc a sa tekcop tsaerb ym nroda ot rewolf tcefrep eht gnikees
.éfac eht edisni secaps rieht ypucco yeht soirt ro soud nI .esroh a
,daeh dewob reh morf pu kool seye nedlog reH
”.drusba sleef gniht elohw siht…naem I
”,rehtie ereh er’uoy yhw wonk t’nod uoY“
,ereh em tup evoL
.ereh rehtona htiw desu saw eciov ym ecnis emit emos neeb s’tI ”?tahW“
ediw srood htiw bulc a fo tuo sllor
”,detpecca neeb sah lasoporp ruoy gniyas m’I“
emussa ot si ekatsim ruoY
reirrab taht tsap neve
,koob ym ot kcab og I erofeb elihw a rof ti drager I
kcab ym hsurb em dniheb wodniw eht gnimarf seirepard ehT
.noitadipert htiw snigeb txen ehT
.tnemesuma rieht fo snoitatsyaw rehto gnissap
,fles eht wonk ylluf t’ntsum eno nevaeh ni neve
si yrots s’yadot dna
.enola em rof si siht wonk I
ezingocer t’nod I egaugnal a ni reehc a tuo llac sevlow owt renroc a nI
.reh rof era uoy dna uoy rof si
.eb dluow taht kcirt a tahW
noitasnes eht ni flesym esol dna tfos era hcihw
,sreilednahc ssalg-deniatS
.nrael ot deliaf dna dnuof eb ot ton saw ti erehw evol thguos ohw nam a tuoba erom gnidaer
”.laer t’nsi ti tuB“
.seliw ni uoy dniw yeht yaw eht fo
.gnippird dna tew m’I .em morf ton tuB
,éfac a ro ,sisao na ni rehtehw taht egdelwonkca deen ylno uoY
seiceps nailammam elpitlum fo surohc ecnad eohs-tfos a tsap gnikaens dna epip-niard a pu m’I
.syawedis daeh reh snrut etoyoc ehT
,ereht ni gniyalp erew uoy emag revetahw ,naem I ,egairraM“
,noitseuq deksanu ym srewsna etoyoc ehT
,ereh su rof enoemos evah lla eW
.siht erofeb erew ew reverehw dnuora gnirednaw llits erew ew elihw desseug ro denaelg ,hturt fo stib tsuj
,niaga debmuccus ylraen gnivah ,woN
,ylgniteelf ,ecno tsuj dekced
.tnassiorc dnomla na si yadot taert ehT
”.owt uoy evael ll’I“
thgin sa kcalb ,eno evah I dna
,sllats rehto eht morf raf
.rehtie taht rebmemer t’nod I
.leviws srae yM ”.ereh neve
,sserp hcnerF eht fo lluh ssalg gnitnilg eht edisni
,shtap niatrec wollof I nehw niaga dehtolc
,eeffoc ym otni kool I
floW_pilS@ rettiwT no dnif nac uoy mohw
”.dne reven yam taht noomyenoh a fo yad tsrif eht si sihT
.pohs eeffoc ym fo yawrood nepo eht ni regnil dna
,stirips lla ekil ,imak reH
”?erofeb uoy wonk I diD“
.mlap ym revo parw sbmuht sa
.krad sseleman eht otni
ti tsap ees nac eno neht dna
.kniw a ekil gnici ,teews dna trat
.ssem a sleef gnihtyreve dna
,ees ot hguone thgirb tsuj si thgil ehT
.dnatsrednu uoy esruoc fO“
,secnatsmucric rehto rednu ,efil rehtona nI
.thgil ylio ni tnilg
”.devol I ohw yltcaxe rebmemer t’nod I“
noisufnoc ym nword ot yliratnemom gnippots
psarg eht ni ytinrete sklaw
,ot evals ecno saw I stnaw revetahW
,won thgir levon tsrif sih ta yawa gniknilp ylwols si eH
ytinifni rof ees taht sllaw ssalg
,kcab syella rednaw I
bmil dewenis morf sevruc swollof taht
.elohw a fo snagro lla
,siri elap a emaceb yks eulb ehT
.toh gnidlacs ot snrut retaw eht dloc yci morf dna
,seiranoitcefnoc eht
,yppah eb ot taht eb yam tI
”.evah ydaerla uoY
.won thgir lufrednow eb dluow ekac eniledaM A .nevaeh fo
,flesym dnuora liat ym lruc I
.wodniw a raen htoob ytpme na ta taes a ekat dna
,duolc ym no ,hguone noos emoh m’I
.detiuqernu netfo dna
ta deliot I tahw rebmemer t’nod I
,kcab nward riahc elgnis
.tcatni yats t’ndluow ti
,detiuqernu evol a fo eow eht sloops ti sa levon ym daer I
.nruter I llit ffo sdnoces eht dekcit sah pohs eeffoc yM
gnitniap-dnas ojavaN a ekil skool taht natfac a evoba gninihs hteet ,gniyaws liat
snetsil ohw erutaerc ylno eht ma I
.éfac sirpyK ot em dloh ot deirt revetahw fo snoitalupinam eht ro
.ecnesse tserup eht tub ,efil a fo sedahs era ereh su fo enoN
.rocéd elpmis eht evol I“ ”.esaelP“
.lufniap ylthgils sti taht esnes I dna
,duolC flesreh dellac ohw etoyoc eht ees dna nrut reven ll’I dnA .eof ro dneirf
.kniht I .gnimoorg dna anut dna
”.naem uoy tahw erus ton m’I“
,deoirt ro ,deriap era
,yad txen eht rof lufepoh
,separd eht fo elkcit eht fo kniht I
,lamron sa no seirrac rab-éfac eht dna
edis ym ta etoyoc eht
.bmurc yegnops tsal eht ot enog noos ,etisiuqxe
.yranoisulcxe ron ,emoclew ton
,nworf ot stnaw etoyoc ehT ”.ton s’ti ,oN“
ti fo ssenidaeh elats eht ta eson ym elknirw I
.nosaer taht rof ti evol uoy dnA“
.llaf dna esir yrd dna tew
?yeht od ,meht llafeb reve sesirprus gnitseretni oN
.s’legnA otni repeed daeh dna esir I os
.éfac sirpyK evol uoy ekil sdnuos tI“
.knalf sti no sirpyK gnidaer ogol fael-revlis sti htiw
etib yreve fo noitasnes detcefrep eht
nialp tpews-dniw a ro
”.kcab uoy evol nac
.em dnuora ria eht ni noitarebiled fo esnes gniyolc a s’erehT
sexof gniraeb losarap dna
thgiarts elzzum reh sdloh ehS
eson ym htaeneb senal gnissorC
.gnissim si gnihtemoS
,tnetni sselthgis htiw dedworc gnieb m’I
.em htiw semoc koob eht tub
,mets mraw sti yb sserp eht pu kcip I
”.won deirram era sirpyK dna uoY“
.ylruos yas I ”,em dewollof uoY“
.eiteews ,em rof t’nsi tnemtimmoC
.swob luftcepser htiw syaw trap dna
,flesti fo dna ni ,edutilos yM
,kniht t’nod I ,dab t’nsi eeffoc ehT .pis I
”?kniht uoy t’nod ,ytilauq gniraedne tsom ruo s’tI .era lla eW“
.smosnart eht ni ssalg hcnerF eht hguorht selbat eht no selppad nus eht yaw eht ekil I“ .mih erongi I
elbisivni ecno ta si taht noitnetta na yb derehtoms gnieb m’I
”.og ot evah eW .oN“
napizram htiw eugnot ym bad taht stnecs htiw sreksihw ym selkcit yrekab A
emarf rood eht tuo gniyahsas ,seod etoyoc ehT
era ew tahw stceffa taht lla rof ,esidarap ni niks ro ruf ro sehtolc egnahc ot sah reven enO
.noitceffa ni em gnisaet si
.desufnoc gnileef naht ssel on
,redluohs ym otni sserac a sehtaerb ria looc dna
.redluohs ym no mraw si nus ehT
?ettedO htiw detsaw emit sih stnemal nnawS erehw trap eht ni demiam yllanrete eb ti lliW
,etoyoc eht yb no thguorb
,swollaws etoyoc ehT
.raeh etiuq t’nac I sgniht gnirepsihw
”?elbissop gnieb ton ti sediseB“
”.ecalp siht naht recin hcuM
,evoba dlog detsaot eht morf sdnuorg gniyrrac
,dnoces a neht ,sessap tnemom A
.detpecca saw evol taht dnA
,yks eht ni eldarc a si taht duolc a si taht tnemtrapa na si emoH
.ereh emit ym lla rof eno ni rorrim a naht erom gnideen llacer t’nod I hguoht si moortser a tahw wonk I
.neppah t’nseod ti tub ,yromem otni edecer dna
sesroh gnipael-egdeh htiw
,stser rood kao dessalg-hcnerF eht hcihw ni emarf rood der-toh tnenimorp eht yb dethgilhgih
,pohs eeffoc eht retne I
.emit gnisolc a fo esnes on si erehT
.pal dna tsehc ym otno sehsalps rehtie looc ton tub gnidlacs etiuq t’nsi taht eeffoc dna
.niaga enim nopu stser wap tfos s’etoyoc ehT
redluohs ym ot wap a srewol ehS
.stops thgirb htiw dethgilhgih dna
?sgniht hsiloof ,yhself hcus serised neve nevaeh ni ohW
sesnes eht dna seye eht sezuag rebmulS
,taes ym ni elttes I oS
.detnarg rof nekat dna debrosba dna
.yaws spih reh woh ees ot tnaw d’I
.kcab nael I sa gnillaf dna gnisir ruf tsehc yrd ym ,hgis dna
.potfoor ot potfoor hgih morf gnipael dna gniknils
morf dna ot yaw rieht no woleb gnillim srehto eht lla no
.sevil s’elpoep detceffa ,sgniht lla fo htaerb eht ,tiinarA
.ecalp siht erofeb emac tahw ni siht ekil evol gnieb reve ereht llacer t’nod I