.don I ”?eerga uoy t’noD
”?yad lla ereh yats annog uoY“
.redluohs eht no em spalc dna shgual eH
,tuoba nups si eh tub ,dnuorg eht ot em gnillup dna
,tixe eht ot tsesolc ,kcab eht ni
,secnereffid ruoy detpecca uoY
.etagnole hteet sih dna
,nalhgoC nehpetS yb ”doG fo bmaL“
,regna ni tuo ekops reven
seitinummoc cifitneics dna lacideM
”.llah ytic ta nwod trecnoc eerf a yojne dna yab eht yb yesom
,seugnot eslaf eb lla lliw yehT
.daeh ym pota loow eht seltsur dna
,ma I erehw gnittiS
”.pihsrow si siht ,ees uoY“
.sgnisselb dna ,snoitcideneb
.daeh ym revo ,rewol
.repap gniraet fo dnuos eht ot ekawa I
edutitta hprom-itnA
”.lluf ot werg tsuj snroh ruoY“ .snoituac eH
,SILIBON arepo-ecaps eht rof nwonk
,yvaeh htob sleef ydob ym dna ,ynoga ni ma I
,peed ,eciov ym dna
,nwod tah ym llup I .suovren ma I
.redluohs ym tuoba mra na sparw drehpehS
,suoretxed dna elbarud tfel era sdnah ym tub
.riah ym hguorht sdnah sih selffur eh erofeb
,tsdim rieht morf srennis eht evomer taht snoitagergnoc esoht lla ta kool
taht sdrow eht kaeps I ,redro fo ecnalbmes a otni sesarhp dna
,elgna s’dnab eht tuo erugif nac I erofeb tub
.erew yllaer uoy ohw decarbme dna ,meht democlew
.derepsihw I ”.srehto otnu oD“
.doow dewang eht ta stniop drehpehS
.mih ta kool ot pots I ”?tahw od dnA“
,rotinom eht no ,flesym ees nac I
.edis sih ot nruter I
.neercs eht no elbisiv ton si eh
,em gnitcetorp si drehpehS tub
noissucrep dna ssab fo gnipmuht ehT
”.ahpyrcopa siht dellac yehT“
.tfel soorednu naelc wef a naht erom evah uoy taht tcaf a rof wonk I“
.ecap laudarg erom raf a ta gnimrofsnart ,skeew dna
kcab sih morf sedolpxe liat sih dna litnu
”.sekatsim seitinamuh gnitcerroC“
,sehceeps fo ruoh sih morf derit dna yrd si eciov s’rehcaerp ehT
.tneloveneb tub gnihtyna era snoitnetni rieht dna ,ni sevom bom eht ,eno sA
,yaw ym seilf enots A
tnatsid dna peed ,seye eulb sih
,hguor emoceb ot derewol yllanif eciov ym dna ,niks ym ssorca detuorps sriah wen dna
,ecalp wen a ot delf uoY“ .piR
esirnus ekil elkniwt ,lufeelg dna gnimoclew tey
,detnaw yteicos tahw etipsed
”.dneirf ruoy m’I“ .piR
,sselpleh eht fo sniatnuom gnirebmalc eht pota dnats lliw
retaw eht ssorca tuo gnikool ma I elihw dna ,ton seod drehpehS tub
,seiromem ym fo stnemom tsrif eht morf
:yojne esaelP   .CSyBsdroW@ sa
,srenoihsirap rehto eht gnoma tnetnocsid dna raef fo srumrum erew erehT
doohtnias desoppus rieht rof
,lla fo tsom tneper ot deen ohw
syad revo dehprom tnuoma lanigiro eht fo niaga flah tsomlA
teef sih ot stoohs drehpehS
.niaga ksa I ”?uoy era tahW“
rettiwT no mih klats ro moc.nalhgocs//:ptth
.gniwolg si drehpehS
,gnorts si tsehc yM
,emot taerg eht dloh sdnah gnikahs yM
,etad ot nageb ,hcruhc lacol eht denioj uoY
,cainam a ekil gniregginS
.tnatsni t’nerew segnahc txen ehT
,noitanimoba na erew uoy dlot gnieb etipsed
,kcab eht ta ecalp ruo ekat eW
,tra fo krow larutan a s’ti
”.ecnatpecca htiw noitaretla eht fo
”.tsohG yloH eht dna
.em tuoba hcum wonk ton od yeht
.raeh ot srehto tnaw yeht tahw kaeps lliw yeht dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,demaerd yeht elihw ,dna peels ot tnew yehT
,tsehc ym ta ti stniop dna nug a sllup enoemoS
.riahc pu llup I sa ,rednow I
.drah tuo-kcor dna elcric a mrof
,nalc ruoy fo tuo dekcik erew uoy
.grebeci eht fo pit eht tsuj era shproM
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.maercs neve ot mih rof niap yb dekcarw oot ydob sih
.elbat gninid ym ta stis drehpehS
,tilps dna nevolc era teef ym dna
.deruop yltneg lio niht ekil
rehtie ni devil ytinamuh fo tser ehT
.ti no tuo mih dellac reve sah eno on tub
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sraey rof gnikaf neeb dah I tahw gnitacilper yltcefrep
.koobparcs eht otni ti seulg eh erofeb ,strons eH
,llew ti sdloh ydob wen ym tub ,ythgiew si
,efil ruoy tuohguorht llA“ .piR
.hcuoc ym ot em sediug dna ,sdon drehpehS
,ecnaraeppa ym degnahc dah I woh tuoba
,em ediseb syawla si drehpehS
.stuohs eH ”!slegna ekil dednuos yehT“
.em ta ti werht tsrif ohw nosrep eht ta ecrof lahtel raen htiw ti snruter dna
,yas ot tahw fo erusnu ma I
.snialpxe eH ”,sihT“
.did reve enoyna fi desirprus eb dluow I dna
.no wehc ot godnroc a setairporppa wohemos eh
.tsetorp ni naorg ton seod hcneb ehT
pu emac meht fo lla dna
.nihtiw morf htrof semoc ,gniyrrac ,duol
.feiler dna eugitaf fo erutxim a ni
.emoc ot erom eb lliw erehT
,noS ,rehtaF eht ot eb
”!ladem eht yob eht eviG !ogniB“
.ylthgil ecnad llits I
,ria eht otni kcits dewehc sih sdloh daetsni tub
.lipup rats ym syawla erew uoY“
”.ydob s’namow a ni deppart
.noitagergnoc eht ssorca yrrebpsar a swolb dna
.flesmih eveiler ot tnof eht ta gnisuap
”.rial s’peehs eht ni gnipeels llits si flow ehT“
.etsap htiw tew llits dna ,yvaeh si tI
,dneirf ylno ym si drehpehS esuaceb ,mih tsniaga ti dloh ton od I tub
,epahs segnahc ecaf siH
.esuba   dna ecneloiv ot del
,lla ti hguorht dna
,tnemom a roF ”!HPROM“
.thginrevo ’dehprom‘ slaudividni dnasuoht derdnuh a revO
,yako eb lliw eh fi ksa I nehW
.elffuhs eht ni tsol saw ti ro
smra ym ni koob ehT
.sdrow fo eciohc sih ta dekcohs ,ksa I ”?em esucxE“
,robhgien no snrut robhgien sa
tnorfretaw eht gnola denil era srodneV
,stnemrag edam ylpaehc
”.ti etah ot tsuj gnihtemos etaerc ton dluoc doG“
.koobparcs eht pu kcip I
,laerehte si ecnelis ehT
.fo duorp si droL ruoy gnihtyreve dna lliks dna evol setartsnomed
,noitanitsed ruo ot yaw-flah elihW
,htiaf ruoy tpek uoY .yaw ruoy ni erew taht selcatsbo eht lla etipsed
,sklat ylerar ohw ,kcab eht ni stis syawla ohw nam gnuoy etiuq eht ma I ,meht oT
.daerpsediw saw aionaraP
,nialp era skram hteet siH
”?hcruhc eht detah syawla ev’uoy yhw s’taht oS“
.yrlewej evisnepxe yllaicifitra dna
,dworc eht htiw evil
.deb ym otno ylefas eno gnuoy eht teg ot eganam ylerab dna
”.sadnega suoirolg nwo rieht tif ot ti detsiwt dna
ni edifnoc I eh si tI
.em ediseb taes ytpme eht otni sedils dneirf ym
sehtolc ni desserd
.tnew ro emac I revenehw ylsuoicipsus em deye
.nam rof nam yb tliub tub ,nam rof doG fo tliub ton si noigileR“
.koobparcs a otni meht setsap dna
,kcen ym hcnerw I dna
,taht seod syawla eH
.erom ecno segnahc ym edih ot decrof ma I dna sdoow eht tixe ew nehw deneddas ma I
.ti yojne ot flesym wolla I os
,deraperp ylurt ma I fi rednow I
.seralced nocaed A
.sraeppa ylsuoiretsym taht teksabetsaw a otni sdrow yloh eht fo stnanmer derettat eht gnipmud
,denettalf tsehc ym nehW
.ytilaer morf yawa nellaf evah ew fi sa
,nrocpop fo gab a sdloh eH
dluoc uoy fi ees ot ,uoy tset ot sruoy ton saw taht ydob a uoy evag eh
,setalp noitcelloc eht tsap sreggaws eH
.spets gnilbmahs ni klaw ot gninrael ma I nehw smra sih tuo sdloh ohw
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.repap fo teehs a pu sdloh dneirf yM
deredrum dna ,desucca
.ekaseman sih ot nika ,god tnaig dna
.sedis sih ta gniws smra gnol siH
,uoy detah eh esuaceb snart ro naibsel uoy ekam ton did eh
--- emoh morf delf dah I ecnis
.dworc eht hguorht ssap eW
,ecnerever htiw detaert erew degnahc erew ohw esoht fo emoS .knalb
,rehtona eno evoL“
.revirpu tsuj si llah ytiC
,tnetsixe-non si dniw eht
,eznorb netlom fo roloc eht si eH
,kcab sih morf daerps evah sgniw taerG
saw sihT     ”. . .eb desselB“
.rab driht eht no talf cisum eht pots dna
.htap detserof a gnola si ti dna
,smrofsnart eh sa mih dnuora ecaps ekam srehto ehT
.su fo rehtie nopu regnif a dial sah eno on dna
ta krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,ylesnemmi flesmih syojne eh dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.raelc dna duol era cinap fo seirc ehT
,tsetorp I hguohtlA
.em fo tnorf ni wep eht tsniaga snael eh sa
.edis s’flow gnuoy eht ta ma I nehT
”.rotaulave ruoy dnA“
,emot eht morf meht sbir
.drehpehS ot netsil ot denrael evah I tub
.snroh ym ot sknaht
.erew uoy wenk syawla uoy nam eht sa wena efil nageb uoy erehw ,noiZ ruoy
,klaw eht morf derit ma I
ecaf ym tub ,seye ym ssorca dnah ym epiw ot tpmetta I .gnorts tey
”.droL eht fo elpmet a gnimrah ma I ,robhgien ym ekirts I fI
derevoc si erutinruf eht daetsni dna sehsid dna yreltuc eht si enoG
,noitamrofsnart lanif ym morf nrow dna dehcterts era taht
.nossel a si gnidlocs a taht
,ygolirt yrruf adanaC-ssorc eht
.flesym fo noisnetxe na naht erom elttil saw ti fi sa
,enihsnus eht yojne ,klaw a ekaT“
,yrtnuoc erom si puorg lacisum dnoces ehT .eno sa evom
.serutaef delesihc sih ssorca
.niaga ffo em stuc eh erofeb ,tsetorp ot nigeb I “-tuB“
,erneg etirovaf ym gnieb ton ti etipsed dna
,nam a erew uoy taht derugif uoy
”.egassem eurt eht evah ton lliw yeht esuaceb ,stsirhC-itna
,meht fo tsom erongi I
,aremac eht ecaf I .em ta selims eH
.sladep eht gnilknirw tuohtiw mets sti morf esor a gnikculp fo elbapac tub
,ynoga ni sehtirw eh sa thguat llup selcsum sih dna
.egami demrofsnart ym fo tser eht enimaxe I sa ,ksa I ”?pup eht s’woH“
.sdnamed ’noigiler‘ ro yteicos taht mron eht tif reven ev’uoy
,niks deznorb sih no sehctac thgil ehT
,edis-yb-edis klaw eW
.shtuoy fo elcric eht tsdima sneppah gnihtemos
,mra dna kcen ym neewteb ecaps eht sllif ylisae dnah siH
rewoP“  nalhgoC nehpetS yb ”doG fo bmaL“
,noitceffa dna erac suoivbo fo edam
”.htap lufituaeb a wonk I ,nom’C“
,egats eht ees ew emit eht yB
,ytic ruo sedivid taht revir eht ot klaw s’ruoh-flah a ylno s’tI
.hgual a sserppus ot evah dna elims I ,rorroh ym etipseD
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,dniheb swollof drehpehS
sesiarp eht sgnis ohw
.edisni tser taht sepolevne fo elip eht ta ylduol gnihgual
.krow sih fo ffo seye sih sekat reven eH
sdnah s’drehpehS .yas ot tahw niatrecnu
,truh yeht taht os selcsum gnillup
”. . .rieht rof sdnuf erom fo deen ni era sthginK lacol ruo taht rebmemer esaelP“
,retaw otni retla stellub eht ees I
”.epoh fo nocaeb a
,eussi eht delkcat yletaidemmi
,ereht fo tuo uoy tog ev’I taht won ,oS“
shtuoy fo noitcelloc llams a dna ,obmoc kcor/klof lacol a si tca tsrif ehT
.htiw nrob neeb dah I taht ydob eht ot gnimrofnoc ton rof ,denodnaba
.gnihserfer dna gnitarogivni
.ecnelis eht secreip egar decudni raef fo yrc tsrif eht neht
,ton ma I gnihtyreve
”.pu ti ekahs ,nom’C“
,srewsna drehpehS ”.sruoy sI“
si em no sdnal taht yarps elttil eht dna
,suoip sevlesmeht redisnoc ohw sloof suopmop esoht lla ta kooL .gnorw nrob era
.soahc eht ees nac ew sa gnol sa rof ti no sehcnum dna
.tekcaj ym otni rehtruf knirhs ot yrt I sa flesym ssorc I
.gnola lla nwonk evah I
,tnih eht gnihctaC
.em tuoba lruc sregnif sih dna
.detale saw I
.gnola thgir gnipoohw dna sdnah sih gnippalc
,eb ot tnaw I gnihtyreve si eH
.em otno thguorb si noitnetta dna ,ylprahs sehceercs enoemoS
.em rof ylwols detrats egnahc ehT
,mih ot noitnetta yna yap enon tey
”?htiaf siht llac yehT“
”.ecnatirehni ruoy morf debburcs
reggirt eht llup yeht nehw tub
,gnorts dna daorb era sredluohs sih tub ,tif rennur si emarf niht siH
.egassem lanigiro s’doG nettogrof ev’yeht taht ,htrow-fles nwo rieht yb dednilb os era yeht tub
,degnahcnu ylevitaler efil rieht deunitnoc hproM eno ylnO
.seye ym erofeb smrofsnart drehpehS
,sdnopser dworc ehT ”.nemA“
”.teg nac I noitavlas eht lla deen I esuaceB“ ”?yhW“ .rewsna I
,rebmemer nac I sa gnol sa rof em htiw neeb sah eH .enola enim dna
.macbew ym fo tnorf ni pots ew dna ,wollof I
,uoy etips ot uoy ekam ton did doG
.ecaf sih dnuorrus tes a dna
.mhtyhr eht ot sevlesruo gnikahs nageb dna
,maerts gnivom eht ssorca elkraps nus eht hctaw eW
”.tey tsuj tsaf oot evom t’noD“
.stcaer eno on ,tnemom a roF
”.keew eht rof doof gnikooc dna ,sehsid ,yrdnuaL .yadnuS s’tI“
,smra ym ni thgil si eH
,elbatrofmoc tub ,looc si ria ehT
”.dlrow siht ni gnikaw shproM wen dna elpoep deracs yrev fo tol a era ereht ,won thgiR“
,su ekil ,sevlesmeht gniyojne tuo era ohw
--- raey a revo rof hcruhc lacol eht htiw neeb evah I hguohtla dna
.rae ym ot enohp a gnidloh ma I dedneterp dna ,daeh ym ot dnah ym pals I ,tsaf gniknihT
,em laer eht eb ot selggurts ym tuoba
”.stnemecnuonna rof woN“
raet sehtolc siH
.piR .srewsna drehpehS
,txen od ot tahw rednow I
.moorhsaw eht otni yaw ym elbmuts I
.tnemtrapa ym ot nruter I
,rotaerc eht fo sdrow eht nekat sah htiaf hcaE
,naruQ degamad a seil ssem eht gnomA
”?yllaer ,uoy era ohW“
.ecnaraeppasid ruo rof rehto eht gnimalb eno hcae
.mih ta drah dna gnol kool I .piR
,dworc eht hguorht klaw I
”.gnidnatsrednu na depoleved uoy ,nis gniklaw a
,eerf si ti dna ,selyts dna senut tsom ot netsil I tub
,su erofeb etis eht ta kooL
,ti strevid ,ti sbarg dneirf ym tub
,tuons a emoceb htuom siH
DI on seirrac pup ehT
.nrob erew uoy tnemom eht morf dereffus uoY !seY“ .sseug I ”?eM“
.smret derocsrednu eht
.txen eb dluow yeht fi derednow yeht sa yvne ro daerd
,ecnatsid eht ni gnis sdrib oN
esoht lla ta kool
em sdnimer ohw eh si tI
.emoceb dah yeht tahw fo dna nwonknu eht fo raef ni
eh si tI .ereht si eh
,nrot si trihs yM
.yaw ruo skool srehsu eht fo eno dna ,repsihw I ”.hsuH“
,dekcom neeb dah I woh tuoba
,soahc eht ot esolc nward era ohw esoht yb deltsoj dna depmub ma I
rohtua dehsilbup esuoh-llams ,erneg-itlum a si ohw
.emalf a ot shtom ekil ecneloiv gnidnepmi eht sdrawot nward
hcihw ,yenom rof yrc rehtona tsuj si tI
,hcterts sbmil siH
.dnah tneloveneb a yb detaerc
.ecaf ym fo lla revoc ot dednapxe dah draeb wen ym dna
,tsap ym tuoba gnihton wonk yehT
,ecnadiug rof gnikool eb lliw yehT
.yarf eht sdrawot em gard ot snigeb neht dna
.tnetsixe-non ro ,deretla rehtie era shtiaf rieht ,denethgirf
,sredluohs ym no tser
.htrib ym fo hself eht ni gnoleb ton od I taht
.tnialpmoc on htiw ydob suoicsnocnu sih tfil I dna
,tlep hcir a otni egnahc sehtolc siH
,dnuos elgnis a gnikam fo elbapac neve ro
”.nac I fI“ .sksa eH
.piR .yltfos kaeps I
,thgin eno seye ym desolc I nehw rorret ot denrut tahT
”?gniod uoy era tahW“
dnatsrednu ot esufer ohw esoht evael I nehw
.seye ruo erofeb ,yllufniap
.noitaerc s’doG lla era ew
.ecnelis eht kaerb eh seod kcans sih fo retnec eht ot nwod nettib sah eh nehw ylno dna
.ylsselerit ,gnikrow speek tsuj drehpehS
.hkanaT deyortsed a dna
.ekal a fo selppir eht ffo gnicnuob
”?yhw rednow reve uoy diD“ .daeh ym don I
,lesrom suoitpmurcs sihT“
.daetsni recorg lacol a gnigguh flesmih sdnif dna
.llam lacol eht ta liater gnikrow ,fo hcum evah t’ndid I gnihtemos si
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup lla
.fles laer ym ot roiretxe ym hctam ot gniyrt neeb ydaerla d’I
,htrof sehcaer enim fo robhgien A
.tsehc ym no loow gnidaerps eht hguorht wolb ezeerb eht tel dna ,trihs ym nepo I
em gnibbarg no tnetni
,daeh ym morf llor yehT
,dezicartso erew srehto tub ,ekil-dog deredisnoc
.daeh ym morf dekconk si tah ym dna
,redluohs ym no sdnah s’drehpehS leef nac I hguohtlA
”.hturt eht meht lleT“
.ralucsum dna nael ma I taht ,loow ym dna sehtolc ym htaenrednu ,wonk I dna
,secalp fo tol a ni democlew t’nera shproM
,neetfif erew uoy nehW“ .piR
,recnad doog a neeb reven evah I
”.noitavlas rof seinnep gnikwah ,meht ot netsiL“
.eb ot tnaem erew uoy ohw emaceb uoy sa neve
.sdirbyh namuh/lamina otni degnahc seidob rieht
em tsal ot sehtolc hguone evah od I ,thgir si eh dna
.tnecselraep hteet sih
.rotinom eht no elbisiv semoceb gnidrocer si metsys ym slangis taht tod der ehT
,depoleved sah eelem A
”.egnahc ot tuoba lla s’tI“ .piR
doG fo sesuoh eht dworc ro swep eht ni tis ohw esoht s’tI
,em ediseb sdnats ohw eh si tI
,sdrow dna sesrev fo egalloc eht ees dna ,ti nepo I
,dnik rieht evoba desiar
.edahs eht dna nus eht fo gnileef eht gniyojne
,yhtlaeh eht rof slatipsoh ekil era yeht
,bmal a tsuj ma I
neht dna ,etunim a naht ssel sekat tI
.sdnah sih morf ti skculp noegip gnissap a dna
.demrahnu ,detselomnu
,rae ym ni eltneg si eciov s’dneirf yM
dlrow eht ni sdnim tseb ehT .delffab erew
,erofeb gnorw em dereets reven sah eH
taerg a ylneddus si eH
,htuom sih morf kcits eht gnivomeR
.tlep gniworg ym gniredisnoc yllaicepse
”.noitaerc ecnis tcerroc %001 ti dah sah eno oN“ .piR
,segap wef a stceles ,elbiB a snepo dneirf yM .skoob nrot ni
.oga shtnom owt naht ssel ,ylneddus ,deneppah tI
.ti gnitteg s’ti dna ,luahrevo na sdeen dlrow ehT .hcruhc ynA“
.ria eht dellif ydaerla sah
.feihcsim otni teg ot ydaer yppup a ekilnu ton ,snirg drehpehS
htap a uoy evag ohw rotaerc a evol
”?serugif cilbup dna sredael dlrow era demrofsnart eht fo tsom taht eciton reve uoy diD“
,tnereffid gnieb ylerem rof elpoep nab taht sehcruhc
daeh sih snrut drehpehS
shtiaf lla fo srehcaerP
.thgirla leef ton od I nehw
.sehcaorppa eh sa no snrut hcihw ,retupmoc ym ot sklaw eH
.keew txen litnu tsael ta
”.krow ym rof tcepser on ,eeS“
,diulf era stnemevom siH
.teef gnignahc eht niatnoc ot elbanu ,edolpxe seohs sih dna
,tnemom eht ecarbme dna ,yats eW
,shgual drehpehS ”.og ew ereH“
,ratla eht sdrawot si kcab siH
.thguoht hcum em nevig sah eno on ,raf oS
,tsugsid fo trons a htiW
.seye ym nepo I ,yliggorG
.tnangidni si enot s’drehpehS
,tuo dnuof neeb evah I raef I
,sesiarf dethgilhgih eht
,moor eht ni esle enoyreve naht rellat si eH
,nus eht sa nedlog
,em dniheb kool I nehw tub
.dehtacsnu segnahc eht devivrus meht fo eno ton tuB“
.teksabdnah a ni lleh sdrawot lerrab yeht sa
,yrovas eht dna teews eht htob fo skcans gnidulcni ,stcudorp suoirav kcoh yeht erehw
.elbaraeb si niap eht tub
.htrae eht sa krad
.ot gniklat ma I ohw ees ot nrut seednetta rehto lareveS .ssih I
.nihtiw morf snrub eh dna
.daeh sih sekahs eh sa gnilggig si eh dna
,loohcs thgin ot tnew
’lamron‘ nrob era ohw ynam oS“
,smialcxe eH ”.eciton ekat dluow dlrow eht taht os enod saw tI“
.suoirolg dna tnaig era yehT .meht leef I
,wohs eht tpurretni smaercs riehT
,nigeb ot tca lanif dna driht eht rof tiaw ew elihW
,mrof namuh sih otni kcab si drehpehS ,lwarb eht fo egde eht ot ti ekam I nehW
.repsihw a evoba tsuj snoitcideneb dna
,mih ekat ot erehwon htiW
.trecnoc eerf eht rof derehtag sah dworc a
,ythgiew si daeh ym tub pu tis I ,kcohs nI
srehsu eht taht daerd eht ekahs t’ndluoc I dna
.etarucca erom neeb reven sah ygolana ehT
,sevom htuom ym tub
noisufnoc eht ni devil
.seenk ym eparcs I nehw em strofmoc ohw eh si tI
.suovren kool I dna
,derevaw reven uoy dna ,yenruoj ot
”.sselwalf si enituor ruoY“ .hgis I
,sredluohs ym sa ediw sa si taht daeh a htiw
.em ot pu sehctac eh ecno ,sksa eH
.syad ruof txen eht rof niar ot gniog s’tI
,enog si ciffart fo bubbuh eht
,secarg niatrec dekcal gnivah
shgual dneirf yM
,gnikaeps eunitnoc t’nseod eH
”?od annog ew era tahw dna ,gniog ew era erehw
”.syob ton ,slrig dekil uoy taht dezilaer uoy ,evlewt erew uoy nehW
.daeh ym fo sedis eht morf tuorps ot nageb taht snroh eht rof gnihton did ti ,sruf esoht deldnah ylisae rozar a hguohtlA
.kcolf eht ni tsol
.suoicsnocnu ,dnuorg eht ot sllaf flow wen eht
.roolf eht ffo era yeht litnu teef sih stfil eh dna
.lepahc eht ot gnimoc ksir gib a si tI
.srood raer nepo eht hguorht sretne ecaf railimaf A
”?hcoom siht eveileb uoy naC“
,strats cisum ehT ”!wonk dluohs I“
dehcte si tnemrednow fo kool a ,em ecaf ot kcab snrut eh nehw dna ,seunitnoc eH
.senil xyno htiw dekaerts seituaeb tnecselraep era dna
.evan eht tixe I ,flesym gnisucxE
.sub eht hctac ot deen on si erehT
.snroh ym ekahs I
.loow munitalp ni derevoc ma I dna ,won deretla ylluf ma I
,nalhgoC nehpetS yb ”doG fo bmaL“
- # -  .ylisae em smialc peels dna ,derit ma I
.loow fo reyal a yb derevoc ylkciht si
,snroh ym htaenrednu morf polf srae yM
rednow I ”?siht nehT“
,teef sih revoc riap a
,desufnoc era yehT“ .suoronos tsomla
,desuollac ,sdnah sih dna
.rof detnuocca dna tcatni sregnif ym lla htiw
.tuohguorht lairetam eht gnitnedni
.sdik eht fo eno si ti tub
kcab eht no sevlesmeht tap dna ,lufhtiaf sa sevlesmeht etarbelec ohw esoht lla ta kool
,desuba ,denetaerht
stnemges eht setsap eh sA .piR
,noitatipicerp fo ecnahc thgils a ylno saw ereht taht detats gninrom siht troper rehtaew ehT ”!pu ti eviL
.dilos dna laer leef yeht dna
,ypareht enomroh trats ot deksa dna ,stnerap ruoy ot tuo emac uoy nehW“ .piR
hgieN fo sedahS 05 ,arepO-porC citore ,ruatneC/namuh eht dna ,)soM-neJ decnuonorp( SOMNEG