.dnoces a rof gnirettulf seye
,edisni deppets eH
.ecar eht now yeht nehw erew yeht tops emas eht ni etoyoc eht ees t'ndid tsomla eh taht seiromem sih ni detcartsid oot tsomla saw eH
,kcab em dekil uoy taht ykcul leef I
"?yeldarB" .egdub t'ndid tI
.emoclew leef em edam uoy dna ,em ot deklat uoY“
,hcamots sih dnuora wap a depparw xof ehT "!FOO"
.nwod yart sih gnicalp mih fo daeha selbat elpuoc a etoyoc gniraew sessalg ynwarcs eht was eH
,dnoces a ni gol eht fo sedis etisoppo no erew syob htoB PMUHT
.dnim sih no llits thgin tsal dah eh eno emas eht
.htaenrednu sevael emos gnikcarc seohs sih
",X rethgiF tiuSahceM ekil uoy looc s'ti kniht I"
.rewsna na rof mih desserp yeldarB "?lleW"
,yllufhsab dias eh
.yllufitip dias eh
,kcab dedlof srae s'yeldarB ".bmud s'tahT"
,nibac eht fo tuo deppils flow gnuoy eht ,ylteiuQ
.reens erutangis sih ni yas xof eht draeh eh
,ylreporp no saw ti os temleh s'xof eht gnitsujda
.oot enif eb dluow taht
.ereh dik tsetrams eht ,ekil er'uoY .bmud si od uoy gnihtoN"
,youb eht dnuora elcric htooms thgit a gnikat
.gnitca saw eh yaw eht ta dessarrabme elttil a tlef yeldarB dna
.pu dessem etoyoc eht dah yllaer eh ,foO .retaw
mra na detrad yeldarB
.nuf os saw taht tub deracs os saw I"
erofeb kcirp s’eldeen eht fo daerd eht saw tI
",eromyna uoy dnuora eb ot dnats t'ndluoc eh esuac ylrae tfel eh draeh I"
,sevlesmeht snibac eht neve ro
.goj a detrats dna gnidih fo tuo tog yeldarB ,seye sih ni sraet htiW
.meht ta gnivaw regnif a htiw
TRONS .tsirw s’taP fo dloh debbarg dna tuo
.wollahs gnihtaerb sih ,deretsulf saw taP
.elbat lluf eht ta gnikool
,ygrene eht gnidiR
,yad lla etoyoc eht diova dluoc eh fi nevE .taP fo seiromem htiw delddir erew meht fo lla tub
.etoyoc eht hcuot ot tnaw t'ndid eh tub ,meht xif ot detnaw yeldarB
.daeha ylneddus erew yeht ,nehT
.mih sdrawot erom tib a dehcni yeldarB
eh dna kcab dedlof srae siH ".gnipeels
.dekcilc ti dna tsirw sih ta nwod dekool eh neht
.drawoc a hcus ekil
"?uoy sekil yelhsA kniht uoY"
,nrut drawkwa na edam raeb dna xof eht elihw
.edis eht ot dekcoc elzzum s'yeldarB
,syob dekil slrig dna
.drawrof meht dehsup dna nwod depoocs rehto eht
”.uoy ssim ot gniog m’I“
.ffo mrots dna sevael fo yrrulf a pu kcik taP draeh eh litnu detiaw dna denetsil tsuJ
.repsihw a evoba tsuj
,hguoht enutrofsim s’taP oT
.koot ti lla s'taht dnA
elihw ecno ta gniklat lla sbuc ysion derdnuh a htiw ,duol yrev
.hgual llams a tuo tel taP ".ereh
.mih dnif ot elbanu ,tuo dellac eh "!tiaW !taP"
nwod demlac yeldarB
lla trid dna sevaelhtiw  pu emac nam eht litnu deneppah ylluf dah tahw dezilaer rehtieN
.taht denrae eh derugif eh tub
.yawa pets a koot neht dna
.sleeh sih no nwod dna pu gnicnuob ,detuohs yeldarB
.tsiaw s'flow eht ot pu tsomla saw ti litnu sevaw eht otni dehcram yeht ,rehtegoT
?miws ot nrael ot rolesnuoc pmac a htiw emit dneps tsuj taP t'ndluoc yhW
.ruf sih no taews eht tsuj saw ydob sih revo lla gnileef saw eh ssentew ykcits ehT !doG knahT
,dias eh nehw pleh t'ndid tI
.eromyna diputs dnuora dnats buc siht hctaw tsuj t’ndluoc eh tub
,etoyoc eht tsap thgiarts nar eH
,gniyas erofeb flow eht ot resolc elttil a tog eh
,syob rehto eht sdrawot daeh sih denrut
.elzzum sih morf elims eht epiw ot elbanu
.dluoc eh tseb sa gnilims ,edis eht ot pets a koot yeldarB ".syawyna
?mih ot siht gniod eh saw yhW
,derettum flow eht
,ffo detrad eh ,retal dnoces A
.etoyoc eht ot resolc elttil a dehcoocs yeldarB
trohs llef ti ,yllufknahT
.retaw eht ni peed oot teg ot evah t'ndluow etoyoc eht os eonac eht fo tnorf eht ta flesmih tup yeldarB ".sniw
.kool deredliweb a htiw yeldarB ta kool ot ylno ,revoc fo tuo emac taP ".reisae
.ecneirepxe dna ega fo ssendedaehlooc eht htiw
:og ot fo thguoht eh taht secalp wef a erew erehT
.skeew eerht tsomla ni taht nees t'ndah eH
.dnim sih fo tuo mih peek t’ndluoc eh
,derettuts etoyoc eht ",yrros m'I —I"
retaw eht fo tuo gnimoc ,dias xof eht
,tpmetta etarepsed a nI
.ti raew ot decrof saw esle enoyreve dna eh tub
.emit gib pu dessem eh wonk ot yeldarB rof hguone saw ti tub ,raf yllaer t'nsaw tI .yawa
,sgniht suoutlumut era ,evol gnuoy dna ,htuoY
,etoyoc eht nevig dah eh taht yad eht retfA .gnileef eno otni lla dellor hsarc rac a erofeb tsuj tcapmi fo ecarb eht dna ,hgih erehwemos morf gnipmuj nehw stug eht fo nrut suoituan eht ,tohs a
.tuo mih denword selddap eht fo kcik eht
,nezorf saw flow ehT
.erus t'nsaw eh fi sa erohs eht tsap tuo dekool eh tub ,deddon taP
.ytpme os airetefac eht ees ot driew tlef tI
.rehtona eno decarbme yletaidemmi neht dna dnas eht otni eonac rieht dellup yehT
.repsihw a evoba tsuj dias etoyoc eht
,taP ot noitcennoc siht tlef tsuj yeldarB
,ylyhs kcab wap sih dellup taP
,hsart yna yawa worht dna ,efildliw eht deef t'now uoy esimorp uoy fi tub ,ot desoppus ton er'uoY"
,smlap s’yeldarB fo edisni delddiwt sbmuht siH
.raef ni nezorf mih gniciton
yart sih pu dekcip eH
.yrots sih dehsinif yllautca reven eh ,revewoH
,puccih eht etipseD
.ecar eht retfa yllaicepse
.noitnetta eht gnitnaw ton
,levon a gnitirw si
,ydob sih fo hcni yreve no doots ruf siH
,kaeps ot tsrif eht saw yeldarB
.sraet sih kcab dloh ot gniyrt ,deksa eh
.looc yllaer s’yelhsA .woW"
roirp setunim ytriht neeb d'tahT
.teknalb eht htaenrednu
"!ti did ew tub ,deneppah ti woh eulc on evah I !ti did eW"
,airetefac eht ot tuo deklaw eH
.sseltniop eb dluow ti wenk eh tub
,nib hsart a dniheb dehcuorc eh sa decar traeh flow ehT
.ylraelc os yad tsrif taht gnirutcip ,pu dekool yeldarB
.tirg llits hteet
dah ohw ,xof eht ot revo dekool syob htoB
.lla ta mih dnif ot ,taP ,dneirf tseb sih tnaw t'ndid eH
.meht tsujdaer ot dah eh dna tuons sih no dekoorc tnew sessalg sih taht egral os saw elims siH
,yletaidemmi nwod tis t'ndid eh hguoht dna
.seert fo hctap llams a saw
,yllufhsab dnuora doots tsuj eH
,etoyoc eht naht reggib hcum os saw yob rehto ehT
,pu teg neve dluoc yeldarB erofeb tub ,tsrif ta nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon taP
gniraeppasid liat s'taP fo pit etihw eht thguac eh
,daerd emos htiw neht dna
,troppus dna pleh fo yhtrow dna lufdeen
.enot dehsuh a ni deksa taP
.ees ot gnirraj tops ytpme eht
,esir ot tey dah nus ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tfel emit fo tol a t'nsaw ereht hguohT
,kcirt eht od ot demees tahT ".ekal
.yas ot dedeen eh tahw yas dna evarb eb ot dah eh gniwonk tub
.edis eht ot gnitlit daeh sih ,elims a ni dekcarc elzzum s'yeldarB ".uoy s'tI—" "—ekil syob eht fo emos draeh I esuaC
.htaerb sih hctac ot gol a fo pot no taes a dnuof yeldarB
",rehtegot yad tsal ruo deniur I yrros yllaer m'I"
,derrits dah yksuh ehT
.pil sih no gniwehc ylsuovren
.ot tnaem eh naht reduol elttil a eciov sih ,deksa eh "?em ekil uoY ?eM"
.mih fo thgis on saw erehT
.elddap eno yhs saw maet rehto eht won dna
,otirrub eht debbarg yeldarB
.sgel sih dessorc dna eert a fo stoor dehtraenu eht no flesmih deppolp eh ,pmuht a htiW
.retaw eht otni staes rieht fo tuo depmuj syob htob dna
.steehs eht rednu morf tuo mih dellup dna swap s’taP gnibbarg ,tuo dehcaer eH
,deliocer etoyoc ehT
.llew sa ecaps edam yltnatculer ohw
.dneirfyob tsrif sih htiw sdnah gnidloh ti derahs yeldarB nehw yllaicepse
.gnimoc detrats seramthgin eht nehw os ylbuoD
.denigami evah dluoc yeldarB naht retsaf yaw
krej latot a tub gnihton neeb ev'uoY
—tsuj saw I .yrros m'I ,oN"
redluohs s’taP revo wap a dekorts ylnO
,ssik tsrif rieht derahs yeht tops eht saw sihT
,rehtnap emit-lluf a
.ecnartne kcab eht tuo dekcud eh sa dellac eh "!retraC ssiM sknahT"
?sbuc rehto eht htiw reccos yalp tsuj etoyoc eht t'ndluoc yhW
.esion hcum oot gnikam ton elihw
.toh elzzum s'flow eht edam taht dna
.trid eht ni edis sih no gnidne yletamitlu erofeb ,htrof dna kcab gnilbbow
”,siht od nac eW !nom'C"
.deb fo tuo mih tog dna
,no tniop taht morF
.etirovaf ym si tiuS gninnuC !huh hU"
,thgir dehcrul syob htoB
.nibac sih sdrawot deklaw dna
.rewsna eht wenk eh derugif eh ,hguoht ,deksa eh "?uoy tuoba woH"
,yrots yracs erom eno ot netsil ot tog neve yehT
.yawa hcni na hcoocs mih dehctaw eh sa worbeye na desiar yeldarB dna
,dias yeldarB ",yrros m'I"
.erofeb yob rehtona gnikil
.dnoces a rof seye sih tuhs annog saw eh dias eh erofeb hguorht yawflah tuoba tog god eht ,oN
.edisni teg ot delbmarcs eh sa erehwyreve retaw pu gnikcik taP
,gnihtyna yas t'ndid taP
,spil sih gnikciL
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.srewohs eht fo renroc eht dnuora
,taP sdrawot kcab gninrut derebmemer yeldarB
.dnuof eb ot tnaw t'ndid eh taht pu dnim sih edam dah eh ,yadretseY
ylkciuq yawa deknay saw tub ,tuo deirc eh
.meht fo daeha llits htuoy rieht htiw erew yeht tahw dna ohw dezilaer ohw esoht yvne netfo
,xof eht ta deralg yeldarB .dereens eh
,yhw wenk yeldarB
.mih ot esnes ekam ot nageb sdrow eht sa elttes ot nageb yeht ,hguoht ylwolS
.noitasrevnoc yllis a revo esnet siht teg ot mih detcepsus t'ndah eh tub ,yhs saw yob rehto eht wenk eH
.swap sih dehcuot retaw eht sa noos sa spets sih derettuts ,revewoh ,taP
.mih dniheb etoyoc on saw ereht ,tpecxE
,edis s'taP gnivael reven fo skeew retfA
.hcneb eht nwod erom tib a devom eh dna delffur ruf s'xof ehT
htiw emit dneps ot detnaw eh taht esle eno on saw ereht
.taes a dnif did eh
.nwod emac xof eno
.wor ot nageb dna selddap rieht koot yob hcae
.taes a ekat ot elba t'nsaw eh ,kcab eht ot tog eh nehw nevE
.rehtegot yad tsal rieht togrof reven yeht dna
.mih rof moor ekam ot ydaer erew yeht ekil demees eno oN
.ylbaresim gniliaf dna elims sih kcab dloh ot gniyrt ,dias eh ",ebyaM"
,taP ecaf ot ydob sih gninruT
.noitanidrooc rieht ron
.esolc mih dezeeuqs eh dna redluohs s'taP revo tnew mra siH
”.uoy od I ekil esle enoyna ekil ll’I kniht t’nod I dna
.reh rof yaw taht leef t'ndid eh tub ,erus rof s'taht ,looc saw ehS .deggurhs yeldarB
mih htiw kcuts tnedicca na gnivah fo raef eht tub
,tuo derettum eh sa ecaf sih dnuora swap htob gnipparw ,liat sih fo og tel taP
”?seybdoog erom oN“
.ti yas ot tnaw t’ndid eh tub
gniyfirret yllaer gnihtemos raeh ot detnaw eH
.taP htiw dah eh tahw saw tahT
.edis sih ot devom dah sdneirf sih fo enoN
.ylneddus detfihs rolesnuoc pmac eht
.detautis erew stip erif eht erehw ot derednaw eH
?ti si retraC ssiM ton s'tI ?dam eb I dluow yhW"
.htgnerts fo yrrulf a mih evag ti ni taP htiw gnizispac eonac eht fo thguoht eht tub
.elcric a ni dnuora gninnips ,sleeh sih no deppoh eH
.wodniw eht sdrawot gnikool ,deksa eh
,thgit swap s’yeldarB otno gnipsalC
.rekcilf eltneg a otni sreksihw sih gnidnes ,ecaf sih no ruf sih hguorht detsug dniW
?pu gniod uoy er'tahW"
,erom cinap ot nageb eh ,dnoces a roF
peels sih fo tuo yletelpmoc mih thguorb meht gnirebmemeR
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“ ,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
.redluohs eht no egdun a mih evag tsuj yeldarB tub ,ylsuovren pil sih tib etoyoc ehT ".em ekil slrig yna kniht t'nod I"
.flesmih fo erusnu ,dias taP "?oN"
,rehtegot emit fo tol a tneps dah taP dna eh erehw erohs eht ees dluoc eh ,tops sih morF
"?peelsa llaf I diD"
,reggib erew raeb dna xof ehT
.trapa sevlesmeht llup ot deganam yeht
.ylsseltiurf nwod meht elttes ot deirt sredael pmac eht
.steehs rieht rednu deldduh ekawa llits lla erew tsom denigami yeldarB hguoht
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.dam eb d’uoy deracs os saw I
.uoy llet nac I fi wonk t'nod I"
dna yad lla mih gnidiova neeb dah yeldarB ?ffuts—
.hguorht wollof ot egaruoc eht gnidnif yllanif ,detrats taP
,citatsce yllauqe saw taP
mih ot derrucco reven ti dna
.nwod gnillaf enoemos fo dnuos eht yb dewollof yletaidemmi
.oot nuf dna ecin er'uoy kniht I"
.erohs eht ot pu gnilwarc
.saw ti ohw wenk taP
,dnoces tilps a roF
.og ot mih dlot xof eht erehw sdrawot ylkciuq gniklaw
.traeh sih gniwollof saw eh esuaceb saw ti wenk eh dna
.dneirf thguartsid sih ees dna dnuora kcits ot hcum oot truh tI
,dnoces a rof desufnoc dekool yeldarB
raews I ,regnol yna ereh dnuora dnats uoy fI
,detuop dna smra sih dessorc eH
,gnihtyna yas t'ndid etoyoc ehT
,redael pmac sih os dna
,kciuq saw erohs eht ot kcab gnitteG
.rehtegot kcuts dah ruf rieht fo emos gniees
srewohs eht dniheb tsuJ
,gnilffins s'etoyoc eht raeh dluoc eH
,gninnur morf deriT
"?dneirfyob ruoy dnif t'naC ?gniyrc uoy yhW"
,yad lla mih ecart ot elba neeb dah taP .ni dehtaerb dna
.syawyna pu er'uoy ecnis gnihtemos uoy xif ll'I .yaw eht fo tuO"
,srepmac rehto eht htiw reccos elttil a deyalp
",oot eybdoog yas ot deracs m’I esuaceb uoy htiw yad lla dneps ot detnaw I ,sseug I"
sllats morf gnitfaw slacimehc ehT
.daeh sih koohs eh
.nwod wols eh did gniraelc a tem eh litnu toN
",ruoh rehtona rof ydaer eb t'now dooF .flesym pu tog tsuj I"
.koohs eonac eht dna
.pu strohs sih peek ot tsuj trihs sih ni kcut ot dah eh dna
.mih rof regnad ni sevlesmeht tup ot gnilliw ton
.taP tuoba kniht tub pleh t’ndluoc eh
"?em tuoba tahW ?eM ?tahW"
.elzzum sih ot regnif a dna
.mih htaenrednu pu srevoc eht detfil
.ekal eht sdrawot srae sih gnikcilf ,dias yeldarB
.retfa eltsihw eht welb yletaidemmi tub ,deksa eH "?ydaeR
sevaw llams eht ta dekool eh sa plug a gnikat
.dehctaw sdneirf sih elihw mih revo gnidnats
,erohs eht sdrawot kcab dednuor yeht sA
.meht neewteb derahs saw feiler fo hgis A
,thgir dna tfel denrut eH
,kciuq gniggaw saw liat s'etoyoc eht woN "?lla taht sI"
.noitnetta sih gnibbarg
skeew tsap esehT"
,selbat llabsoof eht ,dleif reccos eht ,ekal eht yb edilsretaw eht
”?tnaw uoy revetahw od ll’ew dna deb fo tuo teg tsuj ew t’naC
.sevlesmeht ot selims yoc rieht peek ot drah thguof htob hguoht ,desolc s'wam rieht tpek taP dna yeldarB .thgir dna tfel daeh sih gnippilf ,deksa eh
”,oot uoy ssim ot gniog m’I“
.seye reh dellor dna hgis a tuo tel hateehc eht ,seye yppup s’yeldarB eht ot gnilbmurC .dias ehs
dna elcsum a evom t'ndid yeldarB
.erohs eht ot kcab emoc neht dna youb eht tsap tuo seonac eht ekat ot gniog er'uoY
.pu ekohc ot gninnigeb ,detrats yeldarB
.taP did rehtien
.seonac owt eht neewteb doots esoom gib A
"?noos ydaer eb annog doof sI"
.rehto hcae ot sgnileef rieht dettimda yeht erehw tops eht saw siht dezingocer eh taht neht ylno saw tI
.retraC ssiM yrroS"
?sresol uoy htiw su deriap yehT"
.sdoow eht yb dedleihs
tuo deirc taP !KCAWHT
.rehtie eromyna deracs eb ot tnaw t’nod I"
.ylhsiloof nwod dekool tub ,deddon taP
.sresol rehto eht htiw kcab eht ni tis oG"
,rettew deb a ton saw yeldarB
,xof eht revo deppets flow eht
.mih hsur ot evom on edam yeldarB
.em llet nac uoy esruoc fO"
.tniop siht ta od ot tahw erus ton yeldarB
,mih degaruocne eh
dna sevaw eht tub ,detuohs xof eht "!gnitaehc er'uoY" .etunim a nihtiw
,esroh a dna yeldarB neewteb ylkciuq devom etoyoc ehT
",ydaer teg s'tel ,nom'C
.tey tuo saw eno oN
yob a fo draeh reven d'eH
.swap sih ni liat sih gnitsiwt ,dias eh ",enasni saw ti dna yrehcra od reh was I
hcni ot naht rehto dnopser t'ndid taP
.airetefac eht fo edis rehto eht morf dellac retraC ssiM "?yeldarB“
.dam ekil gnilbmert osla saw eh hguoht
,gniyas erofeb ylluferac sdrow sih fo thguoht eH
,pu tnew tsif eno nehw dna
.ylhsipeehs elzzum sih deppid
,esuap drawkwa na saw erehT .deerga eh
,uoy dekil I dias I nehW
,daeherof dna elzzum sih ta depiw eH
.ekal eht fo edis eht ot tog eh sa nees eb ot flesmih wolla t’ndid eh ,sseldrageR
.raews I ,wap ym tuo emac tsuj tI"
.1202 fo yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw
.ydob sih ot depparw liat sih gnipeek
,flow eht edisni deppans gnihtemoS
,sih gnidloh wap eht ta nwod dekool etoyoc ehT ".og t'noD"
.drawnwod daeh sih gninrut tsuj
"!enola su evael
,deerga ,sraet sih fo tsal eht yawa gnipiw ,taP
.noitcerid s'etoyoc eht ni ti dekoob eh ,hsad a nI
.deb sih fo pot no flesmih detaes dna
.hguoht rehtegot yad eht fo tser eht evah llits eW
.taob rieht edisni gnitteg ydaerla erew syob rehto ehT
,gnittis neeb dah yeldarB erehw ot kool did eh emit eht yb dna
.kniht ot ycavirp emos teg dluoc eh wenk eh ecalp ylno eht ot tnew yeldarB
,hcaer ot mih rof daeha raf oot erew yehT .elddap sih htiw
.elbat eht nwod rehtruf tops a ot kcab yart sih gnillup
.ruf sih fo dne eht ta gnilgnad
,ykoops ytterp erew derahs sredael pmac eht seirots ehT
.daeh reh revo tenruf a dna
.krej a gnieb rof yrros m’I“
.moor sih t'nsaw tI
.yrots tsal eno llet ot meht htiw pu deyats ,pac llab a htiw yksuh a
,tib a mriuqs etoyoc eht edam tahT ".gnihtyreve
,tops sih fo tuo depmuj etoyoc ehT "—
"?em ta dam teg t'now uoy esimorp uoY
,dnopser dluoc yob rehtie erofeB
,dehgual xof eht dnuora slrig dna syob ehT
.erew yeht ,tsael tA
.driew elttil a s'tI"
.mih ot netsil t'noD"
,selkna sih pu gnilwarc retaw eht ot nwod dekool taP
.ecalp eht revo lla erew sessalg sih dna
.ecar eht rof enil eht sdrawot mih gnidael ,redluohs sih no bur gnirussaer a taP evag yeldarB ".miws
”yaD tsaL“   :yojne esaelP
,ti tuoba gnikniht saw eh taht won ,yllufhturt dnA
.enola su evael ot uoy tnaw I"
.yob rehto eht morf sehcni elpuoc a gnitteg
,dnoces a ereht deyats eH
.won evael ot dedeen eh wenk eh dna
samajap sih fo tuo tog eh ,ylluferaC
.tcepsorp eht tuoba detanicsaf ,sessalg sih dniheb ediw erew seye s'taP ".enola
.teef sih htaenrednu erew sevael gniwonk ,evom a ekam erad t'ndid eH
,teef sih ot tog etoyoc ehT
,detuohs dna mih htaenrednu xof eht ta dnuora kcab nups eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,mih dniheb gniwollof t'nsaw etoyoc ehT
.tem tsrif dah yeht erehw tops eht saw ti ,lla retfA
.syawyna nar eh tub
.elddap dna ,edisni pmuj ,retaw eht otni seonac ruoy teg ll'uoy ,eltsihw eht tA"
,smoor gnitfarc eht ,egnar yrehcra eht
.yad tsal eht saw siht dna
,tops sih pu evig ot gnitnaw ton ,srae sih dedlof yeldarB
,erohs eht ta gnidnats saw eH
.eciffo ecnadiug eht sdrawot dettort saw eh sa dehctaw yeht dna
.taP htiw did eh ekil
,retal sevlesmeht revocsid nac ohw esoht yvne thgim oot gnuoy eht taht rebmemer ot llew si ti tuB
.gnirettu mih thguac reve yeht fi ffo rae sih detsiwt ev'dluow stnerap sih sdrow
noitcerid gnorw eht denrut eh
,mrots a pu gnisruc yob rehto eht raeh llits dluoc yeldarB .yltsoM
.gnihcaorppa spetstoof erom draeh eh litnu sehsub eht fo tuo lwarc ot ydaer tuoba saw yeldarB
.swap sih neewteb liat sih htiw dnuora gnikool
.taP tih ot tuo elddap sih degnul xof eht
.kcab eht ni tops lausu sih sdrawot gniklaw
.erow srepmac eht lla taht trihs-t dednarb eht dna strohs ikahk eht no tup dna
.reisae neeb ev'dluow ti
moor eht ssorca deklaw eh sa ylthgit rehtegot desrup erew spil s'flow ehT .sbos sih ni nwod dna pu gniog srevoc eht ees dluoc yeldarB tub ,nwod ti peek ot gniyrt saw eH
eonac rehto eht htiw edis-yb-edis erew yeht
,detrons eh ",ereht tuo did uoy tahw was I"
,desiar saw worb reH
.daeh sih dekcud dna ylsuovren delkcuhc taP
noitisop ni kcab depmuls eh erofeb
,daeh sih fo kcab eht ot wap a tup flow ehT
deb sih fo srevoc eht htaenrednu ,enola
.desrever erew selor rieht won
"?yadot edistuo tae I naC"
,dias neht ,dnoces a rof pil sih dewang eH .nuf gnivah dna gnihgual ,edistuo erew srepmac rehto dna pu llits saw nus ehT
.ti gniniur yad elohw eht tneps dah eh dnA
.tnih eht koot etoyoc eht dna
.ees ot detnaw enoyna naht rehtruf hcum
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,dias eh ",taP s’eman yM
.syawyna taP htiw tahc dna pu yats rehtar d’eh esuac dnim t'ndid yeldarB .yltneg gnirons edis eht ot depmuls won saw eh dna
.seenk sih ot llaf yob rehto eht draeh eh sa neve ,evom t'ndluow sgel siH .sevael eht dniheb tsuj gnidih saw eh wenk eh ekil ,tuo deirc taP "!esaelp ,yeldarB"
.emit htderdnuh eht rof mih ot denialpxe eh ",retaw eht hcuot ot evah neve t’now uoY
.ruf sih gniltsirb ria psirc s’nwad
.tsenoh gnieb dneirf tseb sih morf yllaicepse ,ygolopa na dewo saw eh ekil leef t'ndid yeldarB .sessalg sih gnitsujda ,dias taP ",yrros m'I"
.seiromem sih ot kcab nekat saw eh ,niagA
,tniop sih ezisahpme oT ".taP dna em ot
.mih dewo eh tsael eht saw ti
"!gniyrc resol eht ta kool ,woW"
.tsrif doof detnaw eh wenk eh dna ,delgrug hcamots siH
,etoyoC triD yb ”yaD tsaL“ saw sihT
slrig dekil syob erew selur ehT
.edis eht no eldnah eht fo dloh debbarg yeldarB
.seonac derohs eht sdrawot yawa taP dellup tsuj eh ,daetsnI
,deb ot enog dah srepmac rehto eht llA
.mih fo tnorf ni hateehc yltrop a ees ot ylkciuq dnuora gninnips ,pu depmuj flow ehT
,pu daeh sih denrut etoyoc ehT
.nwod daeh sih gnipeek llits
,gnimrifnoc ,nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon yeldarB
.rehto hcae ekil dluoc yeht taht
yeldarB ot kcab neht dna ,meht revo dael rieht gniees
,hguoht pu gnikooL
.mih rof ytip elttil a leef tub pleh t'ndluoc yeldarB
,gnilffuhs a saw erehT
,tem ew yad tsrif eht ecnis revE“
.ekal a otni sllih hguorht gninnur maerts a fo ogol a htiw
.eert a dniheb ydaerla saw eh
.eonac a ni eb annog er’eW .gnimmiws ton er'eW"
",bmud tsuj s'ti ,ot tnaw I"
erofeb mih rof ti denethgit dna tekcajefil s'etoyoc eht no sparts eht fo eno fo dloh debbarg yeldarB ,esolc gnitteG
.taP ot txen wap sih detser dna ,deplug yeldarB ".nuf
.pu teg ot deirt eh fi nwod kcab mih hsup ot ydaer gnikool ,dias xof eht
.etispmac eht otni deklaw eh sa dellac taP
.enoyreve yb tlef gnieb htaerb toh
trihs sih fo kcab dna tnorf eht denwad sdnuorG gnipmaC keerC revliS
.maet sih no eb ot raeb egral a debbarg
flesmih dnuora gnikool
srovaf meht gniod t'nsaw thgiew rieht tub
,eonac eht otni sevlesmeht dellup yeht nehT
.hcamots s'yeldarB edisni mrots a ekil delriws seilfrettub ehT
,yad lla gniod saw eh tahw tuoba thguoht
,duol eb dluow ti yllausU
,gnilddap sih otni thgim sih fo lla tup flow ehT
,gnilias tnew eonac ehT
.gol eht tsniaga depmuht ti sa taeb tfos a
,taes sih koot eh sA
.setadpu erutuf rof
.kcab sih no taP revo gnidnats xof eht ees ot hsub eht dnuora daeh sih dekop yeldarB
.steehs eht htaenrednu deksa eh
mih rof gnikool fo daetsni won thgir gniod eb dluoc eh taht sgniht noillim a erew erehT
ot gnitrats seye ,dias eh
.siht naht gnileef retteb a enigami t'ndluoc eH
.sredael pmac eht lla rof dradnats eht eb ot demees tahT
.dezinorhcnys yltcefrep saw gnilddap rieht dna
.hcuot eht fo diarfa elttil a ,og tel yeldarB dna
,revoc dniheb ylsuoituaC
.gnirons deunitnoc dna
.flow eht morf toof a saw tI
.ti fo tuo tsom eht edam syob htob
.nuf er'uoy dna ecin er'uoy kniht I"
,hguoht erom gnihtyna od dluoc eh erofeb tsuJ
",hctaw ruoy ekil I"
tbuod on saw ereht dna
.X rethgiF tiuSahceM morf s'tI !thgiR !hO"
,devirra stnerap rieht litnu siht ekil mih htiw deb sih ni tis tsuj ot mih deksa taP fi ,tsenoh gnieB
.enola yletelpmoc saw eh ,ecnatsid eht ni srepmac fo sdnuos eht raeh dluoc eh hguohT
eonac rehto eht htiw kcen dna kcen erew yehT
,yawa deppets tsuj yehT
.flow eht ta pu gnikool erofeb ,dias taP
.gnihtyreve rehto hcae llet eW
,ereht saw etoyoc eht ,detcepxe eh ekil dnA
.flesmih ta demahsa erom tlef reven dah eh dna
”.em ot gnihtyreve naem uoY
.emas eht gniod saw etoyoc eht taht
.eenk eno otno gnillaf
.srepmac owt eht ot gninrut ylwols erofeb teef sih ot teg ot dnoces a rof delbmarcs eH
,nehctik eht sdrawot thgiarts tnew retraC ssiM
.retteb ti ees dluoc etoyoc eht taht os mra sih tuo gnidloh ,dias eh
.dnoces a rof gninetfos elzzum s’taP
.egnar yrehcra eht ta eyesllub a tog taP dna
.sknaht teiuq a delbmum dna nwod yart sih tas eH
,eramthgin rehtonA
.esnopser ni don llams a gnitteg ylno ,dias yeldarB
.elpmis era seluR .srepmac thgirlA"
,suoiciled saw maerc eci ehT ".worromot
.pottalf gniraes a otno tuo gge diuqil deruop ehs sa gninrut ton
,pu tnew elddap eno nehW
.uoy ekil attog s’enoemoS"
.thgil gniyd sti ni delkcarc erif ehT
.sehtolc dna ruf sih revo
.sexobrettahc elbarapesni erew yeht
.peelsa tsaf llits erew
hateehc ehT .gnisir tsuj saw nus ehT
,seenk sih tsap yaw pu edor strohs siH
,emal adnik dekool tI
.nosirapmoc ni delap ecar eonac eht fo sgnileef gnizama eht neve dna
"?yeldarB ?ereh uoy erA"
.daeh reh gnikahs ,taht ta delkcuhc retraC ssiM
tsuJ" ,gnikcarc eciov
.ni dnelb ot reisae ti edam ti esuaceb ,hcum os ti dnim t'ndid eh yadoT
.yrd yltsom llits erew steehs siH
dluoc eh sa tsaf sa detnirps eH
,gnol oot dnuora dnats dluoc eh erofeB
”,uoy dekil I wenk I
.gnillup dna eldnah eht fo dloh gnibbarg
.dloh ot hguone looc saw ti litnu swap neewteb htrof dna kcab ti gnissot
”.seybdoog erom oN“
,rood eht dekcolnu retraC ssiM
,ekat-elbuod a did yeldarB
.ffuh yttarb elttil a tuo tel eh dna detsiwt elzzum s'yeldarB ".uoy
.rolesnuoc pmac eht ot sdaeh rieht gninrut ,ezorf syob htoB
,etoyoc eht fo og tel ylkciuq yeldarB
no norpa na dah ehS
,dias ehs ",ti wolla ll'I
,flesmih otni dekool eH
.yob rehto eht ot flesmih dniheb wap a devaw eh
.meht neewteb pag eht desolc dna smra sih dessorcnu eH
,der erew seye siH
,edis etisoppo eht no tog taP
.elzzum s’taP no layarteb etelpmoc fo kool eht tuo ekam dluoc yeldarB
,ekal eht yb tuo gnuh yehT
.taht od dluoc uoy kniht t'ndid I
youb eht ees dluoc yeldarB
",detaehc taht seno eht erew yehT
flesmih gnillup erofeb gnipsag
.flesmih detcelloc etoyoc eht sa hcuot gnihtoos eht deyojne tsuJ
"!detaehc ev'tsum owt uoY"
,etoyoc eht ot kcab denrut yeldarB
",bmud adnik s’ti ,haeY"
",ereh tis nac uoY"
.worromot maerc eci owt uoy teg ll'I dna sevlesruo ot siht peek tsuj ew t'nod yhW"
,daeh sih fo kcab eht ot wap a tup yksuh ehT
ihs emos taht t'nsaw ,lleW
,ekops eh sa stemleh rieht no tup smaet fo stes htoB
,ti timda ot gnitnaw ton ,dehgis flow ehT
.kaeps yob rehto eht did slaem rieht hguorht yawflah tuoba ylno dna ,ecnelis ni tas yehT
,ni klaw ot detrats sbuc rehto ,neht thgiR
.tnemssarrabme ni dekcud elzzum
,dnuorg eht ffo pu teg ot gniyrt etoyoc eht
.llew sa ereht mih rof kool ot kniht dluow taP dna
.maet rehto eht fo daeha ylmrif won erew taP dna yeldarB
.emoh morf yawa saw eh taht gninrom yreve
,nwod os leef ot dneirf sih gnitnaw toN
.hcneb eht no llits saw pmur sih flah ylno os edis eht ot flesmih gnillup
",uoy ni eveileb I“
,nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon xof eht
.enola em teg ot gniyrt syawla s'ehS"
,mih ta deye-ediw derats tsuj yehT
.yeldarB ecaf ot elzzum sih gninrut ,niaga pu dekool etoyoc ehT ".ot tnaw t'nod uoy fi yas ot evah t'nod uoY .yrros m'I"
,detautis erew yeht nehW
,ybrigeK yb daeR
mih dnuora sbuc eht fo lla dna
.pot no tser ot nwod nwo sih thguorb ylwols os reve dna
meht ta gniws ot gniyrt saw xof eht ees ot kcab denrut yeldarB
.rehtona eno gnitrofmoc
.taorht sih ni kcuts sdrow yna tpek ezis s'yob reggib eht tub
.lla ti denigami dnim neddir tliug sih deirrow eh tsrif tA
,hguoht yawa pets a teg dluoc eh erofeB
.dettops gnieb diova ot seert eht dniheb gnipeek ,ekal eht sdrawot decar yeldarB
pmac remmus ta saw buc flow elttil ehT
,hguoht neht tsuJ
mih no gib oot ezis a saw mrofinu siH
.hturt eht saw ti tub ,ti gniyas bmud tlef eH ".taht
,ti sserppus ot deirt eh hguoht neve dna ,pu tnew worb dna srae s'taP
.mih ta kcab delims dna ekahs thgil a mih evag eh
.deracs tog I dna ,tseb eht neeb evah
,flow eht ta pu kcab ,wap eht ta nwod dekool taP ".oot
.yrrow ot gnitrats ydaerla ylbaborp dna pu saw taP taht wenk eh
,traeh sih ni tub ,mih ees t'ndid eH
.noisufnoc ni daeh sih revo decnad srae s'flow ehT
retal semoc yrevocsid fles fo tnemom eht mohw rof su fo esohT
.revo yaw sih gnipmots saw etoyoc eht
.taes sih morf esir ot gnikool ,dias eh
,hgual llams a evag taP
.kcab mih dellup dna ffurcs eht yb xof eht debbarg esoom eht
.flow eht ot os-os ,hguoht
.kniht uoy naht revarb er’uoY .wonk I yob tsetrams eht er’uoY“ ,gniyas erofeb ylluferac sdrow sih revo thguoht eh
.thgit rehto hcae decarbme yeht dna ,dias eh
.flesmih ot gniyrc ylteiuq
.don nrets a evig ot
,tnecs sih edih ot hguone erew
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb ”yaD tsaL“
,keehc sih revo dehs raet A
",oot nekat s'eno tahT"
.meht fo daeha thgir nwod dna pu gnibbob
.rehtnaP emit lluf a ,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer
.srepmac eht fo tser eht rof doof gniraperp ysub saw
.tsehc sih ni llits traeh
",tiuS roivaS ,evif eht fo eno etirovaf ym s'tahT
.tuo deffup tsehc sih htiw meht ot txen pu emac xof eht
.hcneb eht llif ot revo gnihcoocs ,dias xof a ",nekat s'taeS"
.ekal eht otni llaf uoy tel t'now I ,esimorp I" ,gniyas
,derepsihw eh ”,tiaW“
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a ,allevon a
.daeh sih deddon yltnatculer ,kcab dedlof srae dna yretaw seye ,yeldarB ".rehtie
.mih dniheb dneirf sih ta ediw delims eh
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,evig ot tfel gnihton saw ereht nehW
.gaw llams a detrats liat sih
,derepmihw eh sa tekcajefil eht no elkcub a htiw delddif taP
.dlrow evitamronoreteh a ecaf tsum yeht nehw os erom eht lla
.sehsub eht fo tuo dliw tnew eh dna
.mih ta nwod gniralg
.miws ot woh wonk t'nod I"
tca ot yad tsal eht esohc eh
.hguone t'nsaw ti wenk eh nehw neve
",deb ot kcab og ot tnaw t'ndid dna eramthgin a morf pu ekow I
,tuo dekrab xof eht
.tnemnorivne eht ni koot eh sa
.edisni yaw rieht edam htob dna
".gnikahs pots ot swap ym teg t'nac I
,uoy ees t'ndid I fi thguoht tsuj I .eybdoog yas ot dah ew taht seramthgin gnivah tpek I
.sniw seonac rieht fo tuo maet tsriF
.gninniw fo epoh on dah yehT
.retaw eht sdrawot nar flow eht dna rehtegot ti detsioh yehT
.tespu kool t'ndid ehs tub
,hcuot eht ta ylthgils dehcnilf taP
"?em morf gnidih uoy erew yhW"
,deksa ehs ,rae reh fo kcab eht gnihctarcs wap a htiW
,hsub a dniheb dih eh nehw neve ,hguone erus dnA
,ylkciuq nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon etoyoc ehT
,deksa dna pu daeh sih detfil eh ,dehsinif eh erofeB
,seye sih denepo yeldarB etoyoC triD yb
.dlohserht eht dessap yeht erehw tniop eht litnu pu thgir
.sdap sih otni selcric elttil gnicart swalc
"?em tuoba ekil uoy od tahW"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.elzzum sih no gnicnuob sessalg
.sthguoht sih delttes eh sa ecalp otni llef yllaudarg elzzup eht fo seceip eht tub
.sreksihw sih ffo gnikcilf sdaeb raet elpuoc a ,deddon yeldarB
.deb sih no thgirpu
,yaw taht deyats yehT
.elcric a ni dnuora dekool dna
.ezis reh etipsed ,nees reve d’eh hateehc yna sa tsaf
.tey pu saw etoyoc eht fi ees ot gniyrt ,snibac rieht fo tuo gnitteg srepmac rehto eht sdrawot dekeep eh
.dehsaba ylthgils
.pu hctac ot elbanu
",egnellahc laer a evah d'ew thguoht I
.moor sih t'nsaw ti ,oN
.hcuot eht fo hgih eht gnidir llits ,yltnelis delggig yehT
.daehrevo nus yppah ylhsinootrac a saw ereht ,oslA
"?enoyna ekil uoy t’noD
.gnipeels eb dluohs uoY
.mih rof wap a tuo gnidloh
.yksuh tnesba eht ot tip eht ssorca gnirats
.toh gnimaets llits ,etalp a no tas otirrub tsafkaerb A .draug ezeens eht ot pu gniklaw ,ylkciuq dettort flow ehT ".ydaer sdooF"
,meht fo lla revo kcehc tsal eno did esoom ehT
,gnitadimitni yrev leef t'ndid ti hguoht nevE