.dnah s’orteiP no dloh sih gnippord eeL
”,yeteP yeH“  .ni daeh sih keep
tuo dnuof yeht nehw em htiw od at ’nihton detnaw ylimaf yM“  ”…hcum
s’teL ?ew t’ndluohs ,siht tuoba yppah eb dluohs ew ,yrroS“
.redluohs s’orteiP revo dnah sih depard eH .deb
.eeL dias ”,esruoc fO“
”,os sseug I“ .deggurhs orteiP   .dias eh ”,oddiK ,og ay ereht ,lleW“
”?cisum emos no gnittup
,decnad teg aslas emos nees ev’I“ .delkcuhc eeL
,erew yeht erehw deniamer sdnah s’eeL
…woleb dnuorg eht no tuoba gnittilf
.daeh sih koohs eH
,seye sih desolc orteiP
.traeh sih gnippots ylraen noitazilaer eht
ti enod dah eh eveileb ot elbanu
.naem dluoc ti tahw fo deifirret dna
.deredduhs orteiP
.mih ta dekool eeL yaw eht gniees ,kcab deleer neht eH
.ti gnittimda t’nsaw dna ruf yna dah I rehtehw em deksa dna em no denrut ehs ,yllaniF
t’nia erehT“ .deksa eh
”?tuoba ’niklat ay era tahW“
,mrof gnipeels s’eeL dnuof eh ,erehT
.dnuora yks eht otni srood ssalg eht edistuo decnalg ylfeirb orteiP .ynoclab a otno tuo del taht rood ssalg a sa llew sa ,ereht elbat eeffoc a dna hcuoc a esruoc fo saw erehT
,did eh sa dnA .ria niatnuom psirc eht ni dehtaerb eH
”.uoy ot klat mih tel tsuj ,esaelP“ .detsisni eh
.mih dnatsrednu I dna ,em sdnatsrednu eH .onihr a s’eh taht tcaf eht seod rehtien dna ,rettam t’nseod ega siH .resolc nworg ylno ev’ew dnA .neht ecnis niaga dna niaga eeL nees ev’I
,mih dlot dah krahs gib
.deilper orteiP ”,uoy knaht
.dewollaws kwah kcalb ehT
…gnihtemos ees dluow I thguoht I ,timda ot evah I“  .deksa eh
.nees reve dah eh sgninrom tseilevol eht fo eno saw tI
,wonk uoY ?aerdnA rebmemer uoY
,egap ytiniffAruF rieht no
tlef eh neht dna ,pal s’onihr gib eht otni delttes orteiP ,flesmih etipseD
.taht ot teg ll’I .won si eh reverehw
”?pots yas ot nehw wonk I lliw woH“
”ruoma’D ruoJ ereimerP eL“   yojne esaelP
.osrot s’orteiP degguh eH
tfos eciov sih ,dias eh
”,uoy knahT“ .deddon orteiP
.daeherof sih otni sserp spil fo riap a tlef orteiP
”.oot ,cisum doog
.deilper eh ”,os sseug I“
”.ereh s’dneirf ruoY“
.eeL dias ”,eiP
,s’orteiP no dnah sih decalp eeL .noitatiseh
.drawrof gninael ,dias eeL ”…ees I“
”…uoy yaw eht dna ,em ot klat
.eeL tsniaga kcab knas eh sa denruter elims siH
”.ecin yllaer yllautca s’tahT“
:esruoc fo ,lufituaeb saw tI .mih dnuora weiv eht ni koot eh sa rettulf traeh sih tlef eH
dna secnailppa tsetal eht lla dah gniees tsuj saw orteiP hcihw ,nehctik eht sdrawot daeh sih detlit neht eH
ti fi neve ,dnuos sti dekil syawla ev’I“ .orteiP dias
.syad owt tsap eht llew tpels ton dah eH
,s’eeL nihtiw dnah sih decalp ylregnig orteiP
uoy yaw eht dnA …ereht ydob
.orteiP ta nwod gnikool erofeb ,desuap onihr ehT .seye neerg
.ni devil eeL snoitidnoc tahw rof ecnerefer on dah eh esruoc fo os ,nwot ni eeL tem ylno dah orteiP .dekool gnihtyreve nredom woh ta ylthgils gninediw seye sih ,esuoh eht otni deppets orteiP  ----**----  ”…os epoh I“
,gnola emoc uoy neht dna ,detad I slrig eht fo yna sdrawot yaw siht tlef reven ev’I
?maerd a neeb evah taht t’ndluoc yhw ,doG
gnivol tsom eht fo eno ot dehprom noisserpxe s’onihr eht sa dehctaw orteiP daetsnI .yltnahpmuirt
draeh orteiP ,yletaidemmI .yalp desserp eh ,siht htiw dnA  ”.zzaj htooms ekil ay epoH“
dna eeL ta ecnalg tsal eno koot eh erofeb ,MA 40:01 daer
…ereh morf kcab gninrut on s’ereht ,doG hO
.gnirucco yllarutan ton si htiw pu worg ew ecnarongi-fles eht
”!erehwemos ollec olos taht rof nettirw steunim wef a dah hcaB erus m’I“
.eireganeM oirT fo tsiloiv eht dna
ylevitcnitsni orteiP
”,ti rof drow ruoy ekat ll’I“
,tsehc ralucsum s’eeL no dnah eno decalp eh
”,enohpoxas eht eb tsum ti kniht I
.guh a otni orteiP gnillup
”,wonk ll’uoy ,wonk ay nehW“
.ti fo tuo gnihtemos dellup onihr eht sa
,relevart wollef ruoy
.eenk sih no gnitser mraerof sih htiw drawrof gninael
,nevo eht ot revo nar neht eH
.kcart eht dezingocer eh sa noos sa hgual a tuo tel kwah kcalb ehT
elttil yrev enod dah tI
dnah gnidnopserroc s’orteiP ,owt ro dnoces a retfA
.deilper orteiP ”,si ti tahT“
.onihr eht ot kcab gninrut ,deilper kwah kcalb eht
.ssendas ni denetsilg seye sih dna ,detcejed saw tI
slerriuqs laref fo sdnuos eht ,seert eht ni gniprihc sdribgnos eht
,elttil a derrits eH
nottub tsrif eht
taht eno ,onihr eht morf detaidar taht htmraw tcnitsid a deciton osla eh ,revewoH
.nwod gnicnalg ,desuap eH
.orteiP ot txen nwod tas eh
kraM was osla eH
2 traP ,kcezzoW rreH yb
”.ffuts ’lived dna tsul‘
morf lertsek nommoc a dna
.deilper eeL ”,ton ebyam ,ebyaM“
:ni sdnuos eht gnikat ,seye sih desolc eH
deb knub eht no nwod gnittis erofeb
.seog ereH  .hcirdeirF ,noissefnoc ym ot em sdael taht sseug I dnA
.yltfos derepsihw eh ”,dooG“
woh dna dnah s’onihr eht fo leef eht gnirovas
…smra s’onihr eht htiw
.daeh sih koohs kraM
.tahwemos degnahc noisserpxe s’eeL  ”?thgiR…“
.ria eht ni dnah a werht eH ”…kniht I
”…gnorw gniht ylno ehT“
.tsaor eht devrac dna
,traeh sih no dnah a decalp orteiP
.yltneg mra s’orteiP gnittep
.tsehc s’eeL no gnilttes dnah rehto s’orteiP ,seye eht ni rehto hcae dekool orteiP dna eeL ,neht dnA  ”…hguoht ,siht ekil toN“
,cisum eht ot gniyaws eltneg rieht deppots meht fo owt ehT  .dias eh ”…ma I …I“
.resolc orteiP dellup ylpmis eeL
.eeL deksa ”?steunim oN“
,tuo dna ni dehtaerb eH
”?oddik ,’niod ay er’woH“
.niaga uoy ot klat ll’I .ffo rae ruoy gniklat enod m’I sseug I ,lleW
.deb eht ot dekool eh ,neht dnA
.lausu naht retsaf elttil a ecar ot traeh sih gnisuac tbuod ,deddon naiva ehT
s’ti dnA“ .deilper eeL ”,taht ekil ’nihtemos ,haeY“  .deilper orteiP
.gninruter ylwols rorret eht
”?siht tnaw uoy erus ay era
.regnol yna ti yned t’nac I .nem otni m’I .eurt eb attog s’ti wonk I ,eeL ot kcab kniht I sa tuB
.tuoba gniklat saw ehs tahw wonk t’ndid I
…ereht ni tub ,aera eht ni sgnidliub rehto dna hcruhc eht ni nees dah eh tahw nevig aedi emos dah eH
.yletaidemmi tsomla mih ot dednah dna dehsinrag saw etalp eht sa revo ti gnikool orteiP ,ti derrefsnart neht onihr ehT .ti devrac eh sa tsaor eht ta gnikool ,detavilas orteiP
”.em tuoba yaw taht ’nileef htiw gnorw gnihtyna
”…mH“  .detnioppasid ton saw orteiP ,deedni dnA
,delims eeL  .dias eh
”,erofeb enoyna htiw decnad yllaer reven ev’I
.emit elohw eht dah eh kool rednet taht gniniatniam llits eeL ,rehto hcae ta dekool eeL dna orteiP ,ssik eht ekorb yeht nehW
.mih evig enoyna nees reve dah eh snoisserpxe
.ffuts dna ,niaga em ot kaeps reven d’ehs taht em dlot ehs neht dnA
.ylteiuq delkcuhc orteiP  .dias eh
.taht rof ezigolopa at detnaw I dnA“
”,lla retfa ,thgir saw radyag ruoy sseug I“
.daeh sih gnikahs ,seye sih denepo neht eH  ”…neeb ev’I …tsuj I .wonk t’nod I ,doG“
.orteiP ta tuo gnipael retnec eht ni riah fo tfut llams eht
lla rehtie erew enod evah I secnad eht ,llew
er’uoY“ .tinu llaw ybraen eht ni reyalp DC a ot revo tnew eh sa eeL ot denrut neht eH
”.tcepxe thgim uoy naht repaehC“ .nirg tnedifnoc a dehsalf eh sa deilper eeL
”,dluow I kniht I …I“
.ees ot tluciffid
,neht dnA .noisserpxe gnirac s’onihr eht gniees ,eeL ta pu dekool neht eH
”.deracs elttil a llits m’I …tsuj m’I“
.ylthgils gnisaerc kaeb sih ,denworf kwah kcalb ehT  .deksa eeL
.ni gniggid emit on detsaw orteiP
”?wonk ay ,neht ’na won yssubeD elttil a dnim t’nod I“ .deilper eh
…meht ’o eno saw I
,’pots‘ yas si od attog ay lla ,elbatrofmocnu leef
a em dellac ehs ,neht dnA
,kcab gnimaercs emac rorret laitini ehT
”,eip emil yek a taht ekam ot evah thgim uoY“ .delkcuhc orteiP
”,uoy tuoba deirrow s’eH“
.dnah s’eeL otni daeh sih gniwob
.dnah s’onihr eht desaeler orteiP sa deggurhs eH
”.ay ot doog eb ll’I ,yrrow t’noD“
”?uoy erew ,epyt citnamor eht toN“
.onihr eht htiw ssik a gnirahs ,kaeb sih denepo naiva ehT
,hO“ .denedaorb elims s’orteiP
”…on ,oN“ .daeh sih gnikahs ,dewollaws orteiP  ”…ay truh I fI
”.seilimaf rieht ot snoitaler esolc hcus erahs elpoep
.thgil eht nepmad ot hcum gniod ton sniatruc eht
,yeh‘ gnikniht ,detpecca I oS
.esirprus ni gniknilb ,desuap orteiP
?htiw pu nekorb tsuj dah I eno ehT
,revewoh ,etaludom ot nageb ti sA
…onihr lufrewop eht rednu
.seye sih fo tuo peels eht teg ot gniyrt ,deknilb eH .ediw seye sih
dna kciuq snoitom sih ,deddon eH
.onihr eht ta kool ot gninrut ,worbeye na esor orteiP
.daeh sih koohs eH
.htaerb rehtona ni dekcus orteiP  .eeL deksa ”?oS“
,delims onihr ehT  ”…tsaor
,”eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL“ dna
,’ninroM“  .s’onihr eht no gnitser yltneg dnah nwo sih
”?gnihtemos dekooc uoy emussa I“
.daeh sih gnikahs erofeb ,dehgis neht eH
erus ytterp m’I
.delbmur enotirab peed s’eeL ”,ay knahT“
yag a ma ,orteiP ,I dnA
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,kcezzoW rreH yb ”ruoma’D ruoJ ereimerP eL“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     orteiP-
.keehc eht no orteiP gnissik dna nwod flesmih gnillup ,delims eeL
.dias eh ”,nam ,sruoy lla s’eH“
.kraM ta pu dekool orteiP
…llew ,dnA .dnim otni emac sdrow s’ybanraB
.olos etulf lufituaeb a htiw nageb kcart txen eht sa
”.deneppah reve ’nihtyna tegrof ll’ew dna
.esolc mih llup ot hcamots sih ssorca depparw mra s’onihr eht sa
,yawynA .ybanraB ta dekool I woh morf gnimoc ti nees ev’dluohs I sseug I thgisdnih ni hguoht ,neht ytilauxes ym gnitbuod t’nsaw I .thgir saw aerdnA fi deirrow saw I ,neht kcab neve taht mih dlot I dnA .eussi
”?…nialpxe uoy od woh nehT
kcohs ehT .dnoces a rof
.mih htiw yldneirf yrev gnieb krahs eht
.notsoB ni desab naicisum dna retirw a si ohw ,kcezzoW rreH yb ”ruoma’D ruoJ ereimerP eL“ fo
,teiuq neeb ev’I fi yrros m’I …I .htfif eht no eeL htiw xes dah I
htiw mih ta dekool eh yaw eht deciton orteiP dna ,enog saw sworb s’onihr eht fo cra laivoj yllausu ehT
,wonk uoY …mH“  .tsujda ot
.ekal eht ot tuo kcab gnikool ylno
saw ti …did ew tahw htiW“ .yltfos dias eh
.dias eh ”,dnim ym fo tuo deracs neeb tsuj ev’I“
.rethgirb worg ot demees ylno elims s’orteiP  .deksa eeL
.dnim reh tsol dah ehs thguoht I ,emit eht tA
.wodniw eht tuo gnikool ,desuap neht eH
.llef elims siH .dias eh
,meht dniheb rewop eht
.roolf eht ta gnikool ,desuap eH  ”…lamron ton s’tI“
,rehto hcae ta derats yehT
”.lla ta em truh t’ndid uoY“
.htmraw railimaf taht
.edis eht ot decnalg orteiP
”…oga sthgin owt deneppah tahw tuoba gnikniht pots t’nac I …tsuj I“
”,ay truh I diarfa saw I“
”.si ti kniht t’nod I
.eeL deksa ”?oN“  .orteiP dias
kwah kcalb nabuC a fo nos detpoda eht ma
.dias eh ”,yrros m’I“
,yad a ni yawa og ll’ti semitemoS“
denibmoc ezeerb yluJ eht fo htmraw eht
sdnah sih fo eno gnicalp yltneg erofeb ,elims a orteiP evag eeL
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
----**----  .trihs s’onihr eht fo
.ereht raewrednu sih gniees ,deb eht fo egde eht revo dekool neht eH
.elkcuhc teiuq a htiw orteiP dias
.dnuopmoC eht ni ton saw eh erawa
:dne eht ni rettam ton did tI .tsrif ssik eht nageb ohw wonk ton did orteiP
.dewollaws orteiP
,yawa tnew raef siH
,dehsur saw drow ehT ”.stoggaf
.tsaor sih gnitae detrats eh sa delkcuhc eeL
5102 ,8 yluJ  ----**----
,’eep‘ decnuonorp yllacinhcet s’ti wonk uoY“ .deksa eh ”?eiP“
,si yllausu eh sa eltneg saw eH
,naiva na m’I .ylatI
.gnireffo htnom edirP s’yadot rof
didnu naiva eht ,siht htiw dnA
”.wohyna ,wols gnihtyna ton ,lleW“ .dias eh ”,haeY“
deppots traeh nwo sih woh saw tsom deciton eh gniht eht tuB  .seye egral
.pal s’eeL morf gnivom ton ,deddon kwah kcalb ehT
yaw eht dna ,tlef eugnot
”,epicer s’rehtom ym s’tI“ .delims eeL
”?I did ,ay truh t’ndid I“
kcolc edisdeb eht taht deciton yltniaf eH
,owt ro dnoces a rof detatiseh orteiP
”,yeteP ,ecnahc a mih evig tsuJ“
.sdnah gnirolpxe s’rehto hcae ot sehtolc rieht tsol htob dah yeht nehw tniop eht gnirebmemer
.ti ot gniyaws meht fo owt eht
.dias eh ”,ti raeh at dalG“
,ahaH“  ”.si ti tsaf-gninthgil woh nees ev’I“ .dias eh ”,oddik
tfos eht draeh eh taht neht saw tI  .emit
yehT …sageV saL ot kcab denrut sthguoht sih ,neht dnA
,naleuzeneV s’taht
.dnuorgkcab eht ni rojaM talF-A ni ecnedac a ot gnillews yssubeD eht
”…ot lamron eb t’nac tI …tI“
”,oddik ,ot decnad eb ot cisuM“  .deksa orteiP
”.esoht tuoba togrof I“
”,ycnaf sa ton ,wonk t’nod I
.daeh s’naiva eht no ssik a gnitnalp
.daeh sih ni mih dlot eeL sdrow eht detaeper eh
.redluohs s’orteiP no dnah eerf sih gnippals ,deilper eh
.daeh sih koohs eH ”…dna …dna
.diova ot detpmetta d’eh onihr eht fo emarf gnisopmi eht gniees yletaidemmi ,niatruc eht tuo dekool eH
,no deyalp zzaj ehT
.desuap orteiP  .eeL deksa
.yna gnidaf ton elims sih ,dehgis orteiP  ”…oS“
”.tsaor ekil ay epoh I“
…nehT“  ”.em htiw lla fo tsael
tuoba tuo thguorb ti tahw saw derebmemer eh tahw tuB
.kcen s’eeL no dnah a decalp eh sa yna gnidaf ton elims sih ,deddon orteiP
,edistuo thgirb saw tI .wodniw eht hguorht gnimaerts nus eht fo erawa saw eh ,pu ekow orteiP nehW
”.tniop emos ta ,saw ehS“
.ecnatsiser on dereffo eh ,esiwrehto tub
.lairt lufraef a eb nac
.daeh sih gnikahs ,delahxe eH
.tuo dnif ot yaw eno ylno si ereht esoppus I
,yrassecen hguoht ,ti gniddehs dna
.gnilims ,dehgis orteiP
”.ot em tnaw ay fi ,tuo ti erugif ay pleh nac I tuB“ .eeL dias
”.yawa og ot sedaced ekat lliw ti semit rehto
”…ti slian yllaer taht eno t’nsi ereht tub ,ynam os fo kniht nac I“
.resolc deldduh eH
,erus ,tsrif ta truh eeL htiw xeS ?gnikniht I saw lleh eht tahw ,nam :doog tlef dah sdneirflrig-xe ym htiw xes eht thguoht I .hcirdeirF ,doG ym ,tub
.dias eh ”,ton sseug I“
.deggurhs orteiP  .deilper eeL ”,dlrow eht ni citnamor erom gnihton s’erehT“
.ylevisicedni ereht doots eh sa enips sih pu nur llihc a tlef orteiP
.deifilpma ylno saw
”,eiP ,deracs teg lla eW“
.yzzans rehtar dekool
,hgis detnetnoc a htiw ylper ot elba ylno saw naiva ehT
.dias eh ”,yug a er’uoy tuB“
.mih dniheb ynoclab eht no spetstoof
,weiv eht ni koot dna ,seye sih denepo eh
.nwod dekool orteiP ”…tuB“
,arepo ekil I ,ollec eht yalp I
.noitcesdim sih dnuora lla delgnat steehsdeb eht
.dias eh ”…enif oslA“
.don truc a evag yllanif eH
.deddon orteiP  .dias eeL
.ereht hself eht gnisserac yltneg
,keehc sih ot rehtruf ti desserp orteiP ,keehc sih morf yawa dnah eht gniraet fo daetsni dnA
neht dnA .maet a tuo detuocs rehtorb sih elihw ereht gnittis mih tsuj ,noitasrevnoc ecnahc a neeb
reven ev’uoY“ .dias ehs ”…ees I …I“
.emit elttil a rof moor ecitcarp eht ni tis dna tae og ot tpecxe ,nosaer yna rof moor sih tfel ton dah kwah kcalb eht ,emitnaem eht nI
sih yaw eht dna ,ydob ym derolpxe sdnah sih yaw eht dnA …ylwols tnew eh dna
.dias eh ”,yag ton m’I …oS“
.ekatsim a eb ylbissop dluoc doog taht tlef taht gnihtoN .gnihtyna rof
.niaga daorb gniworg elims s’onihr eht
noisrev degdirba na fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
:dnatsrednu ot tnatropmi si tI
.orteiP ta nwod dekool eeL ,dessap emit taht sA
.lanoisuled saw I .thgir saw aerdnA  …eh sa tlef I
”,ti wonk aY“ .delkcuhc eeL
.resolc orteiP degguh eh dna
…tuoba erom gniklat m’I
.moor gnivil evisnapxe tahwemos a otni revo orteiP del dah eeL ,dehsinif saw tsaor eht sa noos sA  ----**----  .tsaor eht eta yeht sa gnihton dias yeht ,os dnA  .deilper eh
taht tuoba lla erew yeht tub ,gnol os rof em htiw ’nivil retfa em evol llits d’yeht taht kniht d’aY“ .ti ni regna fo edis elttil a htiw spahrep
?uoy thguob tsrif I nehw kcab tuoba deklat I namreboD eht
saw ecnamrofrep ym thguoht ehs ,nosaer emos rof tuB
.rettulf traeh ym leef
derebmemer eh nehw tlef orteiP airohpue eht ot nosirapmoc ni delap taht lla tuB
”.sexe ym fo yna htiw siht ekil decnad reven ev’I ,yllautcA“ .denworf eH
.rail a gnieb saw I woh dna ,draeb a gnieb reh enodnoc reven dluow rehtaf reh woh tuoba ecaf ym ni pu welb ehs ,neht dnA
.egap yrruFoS rieht dna
.’ereht tniop a tog s’eibraB ebyam
.moordeb eht fo tuo deppets
.ekal eht fo retaw eht ni dnuora gnivom staob owt ro eno deciton
.lavirra sih ecnis os enod dah eh emit tsrif eht
”?yawa og reve ytniatrecnu eht seoD“
.ekaL revaeB tuo ekam tsuj dluoc eh ecnatsid eht ni dna
,thguat era ew gnihtemos si tI
”,leef I woh sebircsed
.orteiP ot elims a dereffo ylno eeL  .ylteiuq dias eh
.tsehc sih ta thgir dnah sih
zzaj htooms ruoy debme dluow uoy esruoc fO“ .dias eh ”,esruoc fO“
…mih erofeb doof eht fo tnecs eht morf dnA
…detarobale dna sdrow emas esoht desu dah krahs eht woh
.reyalp DC eht fo revoc eht desolc eh sa thgir ,dias eh
,htaerb a ni dekcus orteiP
,trihs s’eeL ot revo devom dnah s’orteiP
”?oddik ,yas ay od tahw oS“
,kaeb eht tsniaga spil sih sserp onihr redlo eht tlef eh ,seye sih desolc orteiP sa noos sa
”…won thgir tuB“ .dias eh ”,spahreP“
”…taht fo erus ton er’uoy dnA“
pees ot demees
”.tnereffid si aslas nabuC“
”.lleh sa deracs m’I
eht tahw ,mih dlot orteiP tahW .aerdnA
.niaga htmraw s’eeL gnileef ,desuap orteiP
.eeL ta gnikool erofeb ,sdnoces wef a retfa dehguoc eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.moor sih fo emarf eht no kconk a yb
.thginot ecalp s’eeL ot kcab gniog m’I
etiuq taht drow a s’ereht fi wonk t’nod I …I“
.orteiP ta nwod dekool neht eH
,eeL yb dessik gnieb retfa ffo nar orteiP ,emit tsaL
.elzzum sih ot pu kaeb s’orteiP detcerid dnah eerf sih erofeb
,kcab sih fo llams eht dniheb delttes sdnah egral eht sa ylthgils hsulf ecaf sih tlef kwah kcalb ehT
”.erus m’I ,woN ?woN“
.tuhs seye sih dezeeuqs eH
”?ay erew ,won ,taht gnitcepxe t’nereW“ .noitcerid
”.doof emos revo erom klat nac ew spahreP“
,flesmih rof tsaor eht fo eceip a devrac neht onihr ehT
.wenk reve I gnihtyreve gninoitseuq ,saw I ereht dnA
,resolc denael eeL
rehtona ot esolc siht eb ot ,tlef ti
,spih s’orteiP no delttes yletaidemmi dnah tahT
.sgnilbis redlo owt evah I dna
.deilper eh ”,nuaf enu’d idim-sèrpa’l à edulerP htiw
saw ohw nam a htiw ,saw I ereht
.ton m’I erus m’I …tsael tA“
.nevaeh ekil saw ti ,doG
.gnikahs naiva eht ,steehs deb sih ni deldduh tas orteiP  2 fo
.eeL ot sey dias yllanif I yhw s’tahT  .yletaidemmi
”,rehtruf uoy htiw ti gnirolpxe …yB“  .orteiP deksa
:revewoh ,sevren s’orteiP esae ot
.daeherof s’orteiP gnissik
.gnilims ,deddon orteiP
teg kaeb sih tlef orteiP ,neht dnA  ”…deracs m’I“
?erom gnihtyna rof ksa dluoc ohW
.kcab srehtaef sih fo emos gnihsurb ,elims a dehsalf neht eH .orteiP dias
”?taht od uoy dluow woh dnA“
,deilper orteiP ”,ebyaM“
.eeL ta pu gnikool ,delffuhs neht orteiP  ”…I“  .deksa eeL
evort noitaicossA llabteksaB yrruF dlo rieht diar ot dediced evah yehT
.gniht elohw eht wonk ot tsrif eht er’uoy dnA .yrots elohw eht uoy llet t’ndid I
.deksa eeL ”?…siht dnA“
.haeY …yaw rehtiE“ .dias eh
”?citnamor si ecnad a kniht uoY“
”,thgir tuoba sdnuos taht
.stneve s’thgin suoiverp eht
,mih dnuora smra s’eeL fo thgiew eht
.moordeb eht otni ti deirrac yeht yaw eht neht dna ,ecnad laitini eht derebmemer eH
.eeL ot saw eh esolc woh gnizilaer neht ylno ,deknilb orteiP  ”?siht ekil yfmoc ay erA“
”?melborp eht s’tahw nehT“
”?oddik ,lufituaeb er’ey taht ay llet reve enoyna diD“
.kraM dias
”…tsaf oot ti koot I ebyaM …neddus os
htmraw taht gnitrofmoc woh tsuj fo noitazilaer a otni detlem esirprus sih tub
,yad s’retniw toh a ot ,oot ,denrut
dloc nar doolb s’orteiP
”,oddik ,thgirla s’tI“ .deggurhs eeL
.tuo dnah sih gnidloh dna don a htiw orteiP gnidrager
”.dnim ni dah eh tahw saw siht kniht t’nod I tub ,yksnijiN yb tellab a otni denrut saw ti wonk I“
.no raewrednu sih gnillup ,tuo deppets eh ,ylwolS
.daeh sih koohs eH
,hE“  .eeL dias ”…zzaj etah ot demialc ohw enoemos rof ,wonk aY …mH“
,plug a htiw ,neht dnA
.delims ylno eeL  ”?thgir
,mih retfa ni deppets eeL
yM …ti otni tog ew sa tub
eirever sih fo tuo dekconk saw eH
.setunim wef a rof yaw siht deniamer yehT
.dettimda eh ”,od I“
.noisserpxe dnik a htiw mih ta gnikool ,saw eh erehT
.gnileef eht thgif ot noitanilcni eht ro lliw eht t’ndah eh ,hguoht ,emit sihT
yrassecen ecaps eht orteiP gnivig
”?ti oder ot ecnahc a dah ay fi
:ecno siht ay ksa annog ylno m’I“
ylimaf ruoy tuoba deklat
”.eip elppa ecin a ekil er’uoY“ .dias eh
”.siht ekil gnicnad wols ot desu oot ton m’I
.srehtaef sih tsniaga
.htrim sti fo emos gnisol elims sih ,edis eht ot decnalg eeL ”…lleW“
.on gniyas tpek ehs tub ,niaga ti od ot detnaw d’I .setad gnirud trapa detfird
?ti ezilaer ot gnol siht em ekat ti did woh ,nam dnA
…ecaf a hcus raew eeL gniees fo
ay fI .og ot tnaw ay sa raf sA“ .eeL dias
”.saklop ro seztlaw
.suovren erom mih edam ti ,gnihtyna fi
htmraw taht tsniaga detlem orteiP dna ,kcab sih tsniaga sserp tug s’eeL fo htmraw eht tlef eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,keehc s’orteiP no sdnah sih fo eno decalp neht eeL
,snoitasnes eht ot denruter dnim sih ,siht tuoba thguoht eh sa dnA
,pu doots eeL sa sdrohc nwod gniyal ,sdnoces wef a retfa ni denioj onaip A
.dnah s’eeL fo dloh a gnibbarg yltneg orteiP
sa etalp sih no ti gnittes
”tooB dna pihW“ fo rohtua eht era yehT
,floWcaM boR si sihT
evig ot drawrof gninael erofeb
.traeh sih no dnah a gnicalp ,drawrof denael eH
,mih ot pu emac retnec gib rieht
no saw ti gniciton neht ylno orteiP
”.retal rof noitasrevnoc esorom eht evas
,tsafkaerb dessim tsuj dah eh dezilaer ylerab ylno eH .emit eht ta gnikool dna enohp sih ta gnicnalg ,desuap eH
gnol a ni dah eh naht yldaorb erom delims eh
.llits resolc orteiP dellup eeL erofeb
,trihs deralloc a no dellup eH
,eman sih desu dah eeL emit tsrif eht saw ti dezilaer kwah kcalb eht taht knilb a htiw saw tI
”…ti t’nsaw taht ,on …truH“
.moor eht edistuo gnilffuhs draeh eH
”.wonk uoy ,knups ruo rof denwoner era snabuC sU“ .dias eh
.yldas erom elttil a denihs seye s’eeL sa
”?wonk uoy ,niap ni si su fo eno fi doog eb annog t’nia tI“ .mraw dna
.efil ym fo ekatsim tseggib eht gnikam saw I thguoht I
,thgin suoiverp eht hguorht dna ,ereht thgir tlef eh yaw eht ni dekaos eH
.deilper eeL ”,yllautnevE“  .deksa eh
,gnihton dias yeht ,ti ekorb eeL nehW
,haeY“  ”.raeh at ekil yeht tahw tuoba egnarts era elpoep emoS“ .deilper eeL
”…t’nac I“ .dias eh ”,yawa oG“
”,ay rof ti nialpxe t’nac I“
dna drawrof gninael erofeb ,deddon eeL
.tluaf ruoy ton s’tI …tsuj I“
,evitcepsrep otni sgniht emos tup eh
.niaga dnim sih hguorht sdrow s’ybanraB nar eh sa demlac saw ti neht tub
.naem I ,I dna aerdnA .emit eno eht xes dah eW …yawynA
…saw ti tahw tub ,deined eb ton dluoc taht ,eeL sdrawot gnihtemos tlef ylniatrec eH
.eeL dias ”,I nac rehtieN“
ro ailartsuA ro iiawaH
.ereht taes a koot orteiP sa retnuoc nehctik eht no tsaor eht gnicalp
.seye sih gnisolc ,dehgis orteiP
.mih htiw gnola thgir orteiP ,nwod gnicnad sih fo ecap eht dewols eeL ,hguoht ,dednuos odnassilg prah a sa noos sA
:siht ay ksa annog ylno m’I“
yaw emas eht thgin tsal od ay dluow
.htaerb sih rednu derettum eh
,won ti enod gnivaH
otni edistuo gnippets
”?ti si ,od I yaw eht leef ot em rof lamron ton s’tI“
dah tI .liated diviv ni derebmemer llits eh taht oottat llabteksab deroloc-wobniar a ot dna
.onihr eht ta pu gnikool ,deknilb orteiP
,deciton eh gniht ylno eht saw siht taht desirprus saw eH .gnieb sih otni
”.siht ekil nehctik a etsaw at norom a eb ot evah d’aY“
,niaga ti deirt ew neht dnA .retsulkcal
.resolc gninael sevlesmeht dnuof eeL dna orteiP
…eeL htiw thgin taht retfa tuB
.dah eh doof fo lufkaeb eht dewollaws eH
deb eht ni tlef eh yaw eht ,osrot s’eeL nwod dellevart dnah sih yaw eht ,sessik eht
”,oot os kniht I ,haeY“
tuoba uoy ot deklat I nehw rebmemer uoY
,selaroM-ittA oinotnA orteiP ,I
.htaerb a ni dekcus orteiP
doog s’ti epoh tsuj I“ .dias eh ”,em ot tnasaelp sdnuos tsaor
.daeh sih koohs eeL
”,eiP ,etanoitceffa s’tI“
.yltnereffid tuo sdnif enoyreve taht em dlot eh
.roolf eht ta nwod gnikool ,dehgis orteiP .orteiP etisoppo
,ti thguac eeL ,sselehtreveN
,deddon neht eeL  .orteiP deksa
doog …woh tsuj dezilaer orteiP ,neht dnA  .saw
.dias eh ”,llew os slliks reh koot uoy taht duorp eb tsum ehS“ .delims orteiP  ”.dlihc gnuoy a saw I nehw em ot ti thguat ehS“ .yldnof dias eh
I …tsuj I ,em raen er’uoy emit yrevE“
’toggaf esac-tesolc‘
.gnilkcuhc erofeb ,desuap orteiP
.flesmih ot tpek eh ,esiwrehtO
.eromyna wonk t’nod I“
”,yaw tseb eht ni taht naem ay epoh I“
.ma I ohw si sihT
eh sa yleerf enihs ot nus eht gniwolla
”,wonk t’nod I …I“  .dias eh
.hcamots sih ni gnilttes saw ti dna enots a mih def dah enoemos taht noitasnes eht htiw decalper ti fo lla
elohw eht tuoba mih dlot I esuaceb ylniam
htmraw eht taht deciton eh hcihw gnirud ,sdnoces wef a detiaw orteiP
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”?’nileef ay era woH …oS“
.yltfos gnihgis ,deddon orteiP
”.gnihtyna deen uoy fi ybbol eht ni tuo eb ll’I“
”…evitcudeS…“  ”…lufyalp ,htoomS
,dnah rehtona fo gnileef eht ni gnilever dna seye sih gnisolc naiva eht ,elttil a ylleb s’orteiP debbur neht eH
lla ton derebmemer evah dluohs I“
lufituaeb s’eeL otni thgir gnikool flesmih dnuof eh dna ,pu delgna
neht dna ,kaeb sih denepo eH
,llef dna esor tsehc s’onihr ehT
.sgnidnuorrus sih ot demotsucca erom werg eh sa ssap ecnelis eht gnittel ,seye sih desolc neht eH
kcab ti ekat reven dluow I ,hguoht
krims ot eeL detcepxe orteiP ,ereH
.tsixe t’ndid yeht ekil detca eh sgnileef nwo sih tuoba lained ni os saw ohw krej lanoisuled a rof draeb a eb ot desufer ehs taht em gnillet erofeb
”.traeh rey ni ylgnorts laer ti leef ll’uoY“ .eeL dias
.kaeb sih no elims thgil a ,eeL ta pu dekool orteiP  .nam
.eeL ta pu gnikool
.cisum eht ot ylwols gniyaws erew yeht gnol erofeb dna
.derepsihw eeL ”,orteiP“
,mih dnuora tpews skrazO eht fo satsiv daorb eht
,’toggaf esac-tesolc‘
.dias eh ”,os epoh I“
.onihr eht ot denrut reppohssarg ehT  ”…t’nac I …I“
seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
ro sageV ni ysub s’eh tub ,siht tuoba gnihtemos swonk ohw tenalp eht no gnieb rehto eno ylno si ereht
.taht gnitirw driew os sleef ti ,doG  .nam
”,teb ll’I“  ”.cisum lacissalc
,dnoces a retfa erutsop sih detfihs onihr ehT
.dehserfer flesmih dnuof eh ,deb eht ni pu tis ot devom eh sa tey dna ,deknilb yliraelb eH
”.yb me‘ rebmemer at deen I esle gnihtyreve tog tsael ta ev’I“
krof a debbarg eeL sa gnihctaw ,tsaor eht ta dekool eH .etalp a mih dednah eeL sa deddon orteiP  ”.oddik ,ni gid ,woN“ .deilper eeL ”,ti ekil ll’ey nokcer I“
.s’eeL htiw tcatnoc otni emac osrot orteiP litnu ,mih sdrawot orteiP dellup eeL ,yltneg yreV
.ekam ot deen I noissefnoc a evah I  ,hcirdeirF
,yletaidemmi ytilauxes nwo sih tuoba wenk eH
”.pleh nac eh ebyam ,llew os kool t’nod uoY“ .dias eh
sa htaerb niatrecnu na ni koot dirbyh ehT .spih s’orteiP no thgir
sih ni ecnalg a gnitsac onihr eht
.meht woleb ekal eht ot gninrut noitnetta rieht ,ecnelis ni doots yehT
”,htimsdrow elttil ay ,gniht eruS“
,on yas ot tuoba saw I sa thgiR
.pal sih otni naiva regnuoy eht dellup dna orteiP debbarg eh erofeb
.yaw etanoitceffa na hcus ni mih gnibbur ,dnah s’eeL
.ecap nwo ym ta og ot gnilliw
”,llehstun a ni sgnirpS akeruE s’taht ,lleW“
:ecnamrofrep s’thgin suoiverp eht ta eeL gniees dessim dah osla eH
…ma I fi tuB“ .orteiP dias
.pu nwohs ton ylpmis dah onihr eht
.ezeerb eht ot tsol tsomla sdrow sih ,dias eh
,yks eht ni duolc a ton saw erehT
,mih derussaer eeL ”,eb t’noD“
.moor eht otni deppets eeL sa seye sih denepo neht orteiP
eht no orteiP ot txen gnittis ,moor eht dessorc eeL ,dnoces a retfA
,lleW ?zzaJ ybanraB
ni hcum derutaef t’nsi
.htaerb ykahs a tuo gnittel ,ni dehtaerb eH
.ecnartne onihr eht gnitnarg dna kaeb sih gninepo
,sdnoces wef a retfA
.ereht od ew tahw ot sa noitanigami ruoy ot ti evael ll’I
.daeherof eht no ssik a orteiP
.ydolem teews a gniyalp enohpoxas a fo dnuos eht
emos htiw ti ta gnikool
tlef ti tnereffid
”,ay struh ’nihtemos fi em llet at diarfa eb t’noD“
,mra s’eeL ssorca enil a decart
.retal uoy ees ll’I
.nus yluJ mraw eht
.yrtne sih nopu mih deteerg taht moor gnivil egral rehtar eht gnirimda dna ni gnippets naiva eht ,orteiP dias ”…huH“
.yldetnetnoc dehgis eh ,siht dezilaer eh sA
ruoy was I dna ,dehctaw I dna miws a rof tnew uoy nehw ,ekal eht no yad taht dnA .od syawla I
.yrd elttil a gnileef htuom sih ,dewollaws
.deilper eH ”,nekat tnioP“
.taht rof ecin adnik s’ti ,yaw rehtiE“
.tuoba gniklat saw I tahw ton s’taht ,on tuB“
.dnah s’eeL psarg ot elbat eht ssorca dehcaer dah eh ,ti wenk eh erofeb dna ,niaga ecno gnisnet dnah sih dnuof eH
,neht dnA .noitasnes elgnis yreve fo seiromem gnibbarg
nwod dewols eeL neht dna ,dedne kcart enohpoxas ehT  .dias eh
”?naem uoy od tahW“ .denworf eeL
ew neht dnA .tluser emas
,fo deracs eb at gnihtyna tog t’nia aY“
,ecnelis ni etunim rehtona tneps meht fo owt ehT
,rood ssalg gnidils eht denepo yltneg eh ,ynoclab eht ot revo gniklaW
wonk t’nod elpoep semitemos dias eh dna
.orteiP dias ”,wonk t’nod I“