…eb dluow ti thguoht I naht retteb neve eb yllautca thgim sihT
.ereht sesrev elbiB ot noitnetta emas eht gniees ,yalpsid no lerappa dna strihs rehto ot dekool neht eH
.trihs egral-artxe eht gnidloh ,moor erots kcab eht morf denruter
!erofeb enod reven ev’I gnihtemos si sniatnuom eht ni arepo gniyalP
.retsaf gnitaeb ylneddus traeh sih ,ni dehtaerb eH
----**----  .ecaep ni no gnitae
.yppah eb ot ecalp a dnuof
,namowselas ttum gnikool-elbatrofmoc rehtar a ot deddon eH
,ytirohtua fo ria na mih evag taht pot talf a ni pu enod saw riah krad s’onihr ehT
?dneirf a tuoba od I yaw eht leef yllamron uoy oD
”.hsoJ em llac tsuJ“ .taog eht dias
.ereh tsomla s’ti ,tsirhC yloH  ,hcirdeirF yeH
,thgilnus eht ni denetsilg tI
,uoy rof ecneirepxe wen a eb d’tI“
.thguoht eh ,eiggA rof gnihtemos teg ot evah I won ,hO .delims kwah kcalb ehT
.drib eht ta dekool eh sa kcar
.kaeb s’orteiP ot tuons sih gnisserp
.ekal eht ot tuo gnikool
”.od ot sgniht nuf fo stol s’ereht erugif I“ .dias eh
”!em rof ffuts ym evom elpoep gnivah ot desu ton m’I“
!em gnissik si eeL !tiaW
.won hcirdeirF si eman ruoy ,ti wercS
.sgnidliub eht fo tsom fo erutcetihcra elyts-dlo rehtar eht fo eton gnikat ,dnuora decnalg orteiP
.flesmih htiw desaelp rehtar gnileef
.orteiP ot txen elbat eht ta gnitniop ,deggurhs neht eH
”?taht od d’uoY“ .deknilb orteiP
,deggurhs ylpmis eH
”?uoy rof ysub oot ytiC“
.deksa eh ”?ecalp elttil siht
?yawyna ,rof taht ekil mih ta gnikool neve uoy erew lleh ehT .pal
.retfa gninrom eht siht gnitteg er’uoy yrroS
roolf eht ta gnikool ,yawa denrut kwah kcalb ehT
.11:92 haimereJ detouq taht strihs ot kcab gninrut ,deddon orteiP
tsuj s’tI …htiw neeb ev’uoy slrig esoht lla
!remmus eht revo boj a tog yllautca I ?tahw sseug ,haeY
”.nwot ecin a s’ti ,nees ev’I tahw morF“ .eeL dias
”,retaw hserf ni maws yllaer reven I …hE“
,hcirdeirF yeH  5102 ,02 enuJ  ----**----  .did eh sa
…s’eH .taht ta eno doog nmad a dnA .dneirf a s’eH
tuo dna ni dehtaerb eh tub ,tcatnoc eht ta tib elttil a desaercni etar traeh s’orteiP .sredluohs depmub yeht os orteiP gnillup ,dias eh
”,yug gib ,riohc eht ot hcaerp uoY“
”?wohs eht retfA .emit tog I ,haeY“
”ruoma’D ruoJ ereimerP eL“ fo noisrev degdirba na fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”,taht ekil gnihtemos ,haeY“
.yawa teef wef a ecafrus eht gnikaerb erofeb dnoces a rof gnigrembus ,kcod eht desaeler neht eH .deilper eeL
”.deb ot teg attog ev’I
.deilper orteiP ”,yletal ydoom tib a neeb tsuj ev’I sseuG …hE“
.deneppah reve ti tegrof ll’eh dnA
”.skrow taht nokcer I .haeY“ .dias eh ”,haeY“
”.ereht kcab did reve I naht ereh emoh ta erom leef I .gniht doog a s’ti sseug I“ .deggurhs eH
.detnemmoc orteiP ”,peY“
.artsehcro eht morf sdneirf sih fo rehtona did sa ,rac eht fo tuo
”,erus m’I ,meht ot desu worg lliw uoY“
----**----  .gniretne dna yrotimrod eht ot gninrut erofeb ,deggurhs eH
…deklat reve ylno ev’ew
.riahc sih ni kcab gninael ,delims orteiP ”.peY“  ”.sniatnuom
,ega ym eciwt revo s’eh
,hcirdeirF  5102 ,32 enuJ
.egde eht no detser smra sih os pu flesmih gnillup dna kcod eht ot revo gnimmiws
.teerts eht fo ruotnoc eht wollof ot devruc taht swodniw htiw pohs a saw noitnetta sih thguac tsom taht gniht eht tuB
.mih ta tuo gnippop tnecca nrehtuoS thgil a
.worraps eht ot denrut neht eH
.deksa eh ”?tuoba ’niklat ew erew tahw ,yawynA“
”.llih eht fo pot eht ta letoh detnuah a neve s’erehT
”.yks thgin eht ni srats ynam os nees reve ev’I fi wonk t’nod I ,wonk uoY“
”.raey siht reilrae tfarD ABF eht rof deralced yllautca eH“
,thgiliwt eht ni delkniwt seye sih yaw ehT
,lleW“  .gnidliub gnikool-yrotimrod eht fo tnorf ni thgir
”.yug ’nitseretni yrev a ekil mees aY“
.resolc orteiP gnillup ,deddon eeL
…tae ot secalp fo stol ,srinevuos
.nialpxe yllaer ton
,seye sih desolc eH
,daor eht dessorc ydaerla dah orteiP tuB  ”!tiaw ,orteiP“
.deciton neve ton dah eh ereht noisnet tuo gnikahs ,tuo sdnah sih koohs neht eH  ?thgir ,yag
,ylsuovren delkcuhc orteiP
.rorret reehs yb decalper saw gnileef mraw sih sa
.boj emosewa ytterp a ekil sdnuos
saw hcihw ,teerts eht ssorca rab euqselrub a was neve eH
.hciwdnas sih ot denrut kwah kcalb eht ,neht dnA
”.ylevol s’ti ,yas tsum I“
.ti ees ll’ydobon erehw erehwemos
.kcab denael eh sa orteiP dias
.eeL ta pu gnikool ,deknilb orteiP
.eeL dias ”,dnammoc ay sA“
”,stsiruot ot desu lla er’yeht teB“
”,era uoy sa tliub sa ton s’eH“
,erots eht fo tuo gniklaw erofeb ti koot orteiP dna ,gab a ni trihs eht decalp ttum eht ,siht htiW
?wonk’y ,seiruj ym rof deraperp karovD eht teg attoG
,redluohs s’orteiP dnuora mra na depard eH
,daeh sih koohs kwah kcalb ehT  ”?…uoy era ,orteiP“
.detnemmoc orteiP
”.rehtorb redlo ym rof tfig a rof gnikool yltsom m’I ,lleW“ .deggurhs eH
”…wonk tsum uoy fi ,lleW“
,koobetoN noitisopmoC eht ,hcirdeirF
.ffo flesmih yrd ot nageb neht eH
…tib a deklat ew oS .arepo eht rof ereht saw I taht gniht eht denoitnem I dna ,tnadnetta erots a s’eH .eeL saw ereht dnA
gnicnartne gnihtemos saw erehT
,od ot deen I strecnoc eht lla s’ereht neht dnA
.deggurhs eH ”…ygrene
”,me‘ emalb t’nac I ,imaiM ni evil ay fi ,lleW“
.laed taerg a mih desirprus taht gnihtemos
.hguoht ,ecin eb tsuM“ .deggurhs eH
,liam eht ni emoc ot sdeen tahT
.alotnereneC fo ecnamrofrep tsrif ruo evah ew worromot ,yawyna ,lleW
dnA“ .tsirw sih no dnah a decalp
”,yllaer toN“ .deggurhs orteiP
”,nwot ylevol a s’tI“  ”.ecalp siht gnitcepxe t’nsaw I“
”.elbuort yna t’nia ti ,em tsurT“
.taerg eb annog si siht ,hcirdeirF ,yawynA
”.si thgin eht lufituaeb woh tuoba gnikniht tsuJ“
.dedeen I tahw yltcaxe saw syad wef a rof yawa gnioG
.eeL dias ”,t’nod yeht tahT“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.egap yrruFoS rieht dna
.oot ,ti otni gnitteg era elpoep smees tI
.deilper taog eht
…s’tI .ti etah ylbaborp d’uoY“
”.taht ekil gnihtyna ro sekal mad tnaig yna tuoba gnihton ylniatreC“
.gninoitidnoc ria on dah ew nehw syad eht gnirud ereh t’nerew uoy lufknaht eB“
.nwod delooc evah sgnihT .haey
”.thgin yreve ereht eb ll’uoy snaem tsuj taht ,lleW
”.ereh tuo dloc yllufwa s’retaW“ .dias eh
.leef mih edam ssenesolc s’eeL woh
.esac ollec sih debbarg eh sa yltfos gnilkcuhc ,dehgis orteiP
.mih ta nwod gnikool onihr eht
”tooB dna pihW“ fo rohtua eht era yehT
”?erolpxe ot ffo er’ew sseug I ,yad eht fo tsom tog ev’ew ecnis ,oS“
.eeL ecaf ot denrut eH
.srats eht ta pu gnikool ,delims eH .eeL dias
,deciton neeb erofeb reven sah hcihw
…deciton eh kniht t’nod I ,dooG
”.hsoJ ,yako neeb s’ti ,yas ot evaH“
.deksa eh ”?taht saw tahW“
.dellews mih nihtiw gnihtemos ,deneppah tahw wenk eh erofeb dna ,denediw seye s’kwah kcalb ehT
”?yhW“ .orteiP dias ”,oN“
neht eH  .gnihgis erofeb ,reh dehctaw kwah kcalb ehT
.ynnacnu fo dnik s’ti ,og I erehwyreve
”?…drib kcalB .era uoy drib ’o dnik tahw onnud I“ .delims eH ”.sgnirpS
”.netfo oot ecalp at ecalp morf devom t’nevah I dnA .melborp eht si ,snwod fo tol a dah s’tI“ .dehgis eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.taht fo gnikniht er’uoy yhw erus toN“
.tluser a sa flesmih tuoba tuo sdnif eh tahw dna
.taht lla dna seow retsemes fo dnE
.dias eh ”,gniht eruS“
.moolb lluf ni srewolf fo stros lla htiw
.teiuq tib a neeb ev’I fi yrroS
.eeL deksa ”?orteiP“  ”?…tahW“
.deilper eeL ”,tib A“  .orteiP deksa
”.gnihtemos ro retaw emos teg
”,lliw I erus m’I“
.daeh reh koohs revird ehT
”…tub ,gnisworb tsuj m’I“
.snoitpac trihs enimaxe ot nageb eh sa mih ta thgir gniddon orteiP ,delims eH
.hguoht ,yaw rehto yna ti evah t’ndluow I
,tsehc ym ffo taht teg ot dedeen I .wonk t’nod I  ?thgiR
”.eb ot sdneirf artsehcro ruoy fo emos rof kcab og ot tog ev’I“ .dias ehs
.dias eh ”,oddik ,did I tahT“
.deggurhs onihr ehT
ttum ehT  ”.dnoces a tsuj emmiG“ .ecaf reh fo tuo riah ednolb emos gnihsurb ,ttum eht
”.secnamrofrep eht trats ot tuoba er’ew taht won
.kcod llams a no tas eh erehw orteiP ta revo gnikool ,ekal eht fo ecafrus eht ekorb eeL sa dehctaw eh ,erehT
,hO  .sdne loohcs erofeb yllufepoh dna
.elims sselhtoot a orteiP evag eeL
…naem I ?ehs t’nsi ,yzarc s’ehS .gnihtemos tuoba ’lained ni‘ m’I gniyas speek tsuj aerdnA ,naem I .wonk t’nod I
.rac reh deretne rodarbaL eht ,siht htiW  ”.llew sa uoy dnA“  ”.erac
deppots rac eht tub ,sgnidliub rehto erew retaeht eht dnoyeB
”?sdrawretfa tuo gnah at snalp yna tog ay :’nirednow m’I ,oddik ,yaS“ .orteiP ot denrut neht eH
.yawa gnikool ,daeh sih koohs eH
traeh sih ,etalitnevrepyh ot nageb orteiP ,ekorb ssik eht sA
,gninrom eht ni esraeher t’nod ew erehw syad evah ot gniog er’eW“ .dias eh
.orteiP dias ”,ekil skool tI“
”,kraM ,I saw rehtieN“
.dias eh ”,ereht llits er’yeht ,yrrow t’noD“ .dekcap dah eeL wenk eh sehciwdnas nairategev eht dettap orteiP  ”.em
”.yawyna ,meht fo eno ,lleW“ .gurhs a htiw hsoJ ot kcab derutseg eH .dias eh
sih morf dah eh noitcartta fo sthguoht revetahw dehsinab eh sa
.rodarbaL eht dias
onihr ralucsum rehtar a
?huh ,taht yb em gnillac llitS
.erac ekat uoY“ .dias eh
.mih no thgit elttil a saw taht trihs a ni
.sneppah ffuts nehw niaga uoy ot klat ll’I sseug I ,yawynA
.ot ffo deklaw dah eeL erehw ot kcab gninrut
,onihr eht ot rebmun enohp sih deyaler neht eH
.orteiP ot tuo dnah thgir sih dleh neht eH .dias eh ”,oddik ,og ay ereht ,llew ,heH“  ”.ecalp
.dias eh ”,oddik ,ecafrus eht ’nihctarcs neve t’nia tahT“
”?huh ,sgnirpS akeruE fo nwot eht si siht dnA“
.taorht sih ni pmul a gniwollaws ,deddon orteiP
.yltsenoh ,revetahw s’ti
”.ereht nwod ecalp azzip a s’ereht
.eeL ta gnikool ,delkcuhc eH
”.flesruoy fo erac ekat aY“
,tahW“ .deknilb orteiP
.onihr eht deksa ”?egral-artxe nI“
…gnol oot dnoces a tsuj
,ecnelis fo tnemom a derahs neht yehT
.delkcuhc eeL  .deksa eh
.revo dellup revird eht sa wodniw eht ot esolc gninael orteiP
dluoc eh taht tnemeticxe
”?naf arepO“ .deknilb orteiP
”?egnar ruoy s’tahw oS“
.deilper orteiP ”,tnellecxE“
----**----  .traeh gnitaeb sih mlac ot yrt
.thgin gninepo rof tiaw t’naC
t’nod I .suoregnad sdaor eht sekam wons eht tub
.erutalucsum sih fo sevruc eht gnithgilhgih retaw eht
,delkcuhc kwah kcalb ehT
?mih evag uoy kool taht saw lleh eht tahW .laed gib ,onihr tew ,eruS
?draob dna moor eerf sulp skcub dnasuoht a ,naem I
.oot ,emosdnah etiuq dnA
.ylthgil ti gnihcuot dna ssalg eht ot pu gnimoc dnah sih
,erehwon fo elddim eht ni tuo s’tI
.tuo decnalg neht eH
,yag ton er’uoy ,yag ton er’uoY
.dnuopmoc eht morf daor eht ssorca tsuj tniopweiv a no doots htob yehT
…yug ecin a si yllaer eH …mH
,pu ti gnar ylkciuq ehS
retaw eht ,taht ekil tew eeL fo thgis eht ta erats dluoc eh ekil
”.’nileef taht wonk t’nseod ohw nam das a s’tI“ .dias eeL
.teerts eht pu dekool neht eH
,kcezzoW rreH yb
,yawa dellup eh ,neht dnA
…fo dnik egnarts a tlef osla eh hguoht
.doog ytterp tlef ti dna ,efil ym ni
.eeL ta kool ot denrut orteiP
.sgnirpS akeruE ni ereh ’niod er’uoy tahw em llet t’nseod taht tub ,ereh er’ey yhw srewsna taht ,lleW“
.deksa eh ”?ereh emac ay nehw aera siht tuoba gnihtyna daer neve ay diD“
.tuo esactius eht dellup eh sa daeh sih gnikahs ,seye sih dellor orteiP
,hE  ?thgir ,esnes sekam taht esuaC‘ .ataivarT htiw gnitrats er’ew esruoc fo dnA
.trid eht tsniaga nolat sih gnippat ,deggurhs eH
.rehtie ,ti tuoba yas ot gnihtyna dah yllaer wenk I ydoboN“ .dias eh
”.riohc eht ot hcaerp uoY“
tnaem kool taht ,haeY
.rac eht morf yawa deppets eh sa delims ,reppohssarg gnikool-yrps rehtar a
efil a evil ot ecnereffid a sekam tI
.lufsserts saw loohcs hgih thguoht I dnA
”.srallod evif-ytrof ot tuo emoc ll’tahT“
pu dedne su fo owt eht ,wohemos ,neht dnA .pu dewohs eeL
”?skrazO eht ni arepO rof ereh er’uoY“
.looc ti yalp tsuJ
…maerd a t’nsaw taht ,doG ym hO  …  ----**----  PLEH
”…ton llahs I ,drehpehs ym si droL ehT“
.onihr eht ta revo gnikool ,hsoJ dias
,egap ytiniffAruF rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
,raef ni retsaf taeb ot nageb traeh siH
.tuo decnalg eH .deilper orteiP ”,gniddik oN“
.orteiP ot delims neht eH
.orteiP ot txen pu deklaw eh sa gnihctiwt eannetna sih ,kraM dias
.daeh sih koohs orteiP
.og uoy ereht tub ,skrazO sasnakrA ’niggirf eht
.teerts eht ssorca gnihsad ,denrut eh gninraw rehtruf tuohtiw dna ,siht delbmum yldeirruh orteiP
.tuo gnikool ,delims eH .deilper orteiP
.dias eh ”,yletamitni taht wonk uoy ekil dnuos uoY“
.retsiger hsac eht ot gniklaw ,deddon orteiP
.onihr eht ta gnikool orteiP
”,dneirf a er’uoY“  ”—t’nod I …naem I“ .orteiP dias ”,t’ndluohs uoy ,hO“
.ees I“ .onihr eht deksa
----**----  .sdnuorg eht no airetefac eht ot
”.ereht em fo ytnelp gniees eb ll’uoy ,yeh
.ti evah uoy ereht tub ,onihr egral a ni taht tcepxe t’nod uoY
.yldaorb gnilims ,kcab denael ehS
.eeL dias ”,thgir ,hA“
”.oddik ,wohs eht retfa ay ees ll’I
.dias eh ”,os yas uoy fI …fI“
ev’uoY“ .deilper orteiP ”,doog s’tahT“  ”.gnoleb
”!tuo ollec ruoy teg uoy pleh em tel tsael tA“
hciwdnas sih tae ot gniunitnoc
”?ezis trihs sih s’tahW“ .dias eh
.sregnif sih ta gnikcip yldi ,desuap eH
”,ediug a gnivah etaicerppa d’I kniht I“ .delims orteiP
.artsehcro tip a ni gniyalp boj a tog I
teg ot secalp fo stoL
”,lamrof oot s’taht ,esaelP“
…driew s’ti ,lanruoJ ,wonk uoY  .revetahW
”,ti eveileb retteb aY“
,ylreporp gninoitcnuf ton saw gninoitidnoc ria eht taht tcaf eht etipsed ,ereht dnA
…drows eht naht reithgim saw nep eht yas did syawla yehT
.strihs gniyrav eht ta dnuora gnikool ,nihc sih debbur onihr ehT ”…mH“  .detnemmoc orteiP ”,egral-artxE“
,lanruoj yeH  5102 ,31 lirpA  2 fo 1 traP ,kcezzoW rreH yb ”ruoma’D ruoJ ereimerP eL“   yojne esaelP
”!si ti wohs eht retfa nehT“
.yldaorb oot elttil a spahrep gnilims ,deggurhs orteiP
.tip eht fo tuo gnidaeh saw artsehcro eht erehw ot pu dekool neht eH
ti dna ,hguoht ,skrazO sasnakrA eht ni tuo s’tI
.redluohs s’orteiP no dnah a gnicalp ,deddon eeL
…kcuf yloH  …deneppah lla tI
erofeb xes dah ev’I
.erots eht otni gnippets
.ay peek t’ndluohs I ,yrroS“
”,oddik ,thgir eb thgim uoY“
fo elddim eht ni arepo gniyalp elihw dneirf gnitseretni na teem ot teg d’I thguoht reven I .ecin yllaer s’eh tub
”.hcaeb eht ot desu ooT“
.dias ehs ”,trihs taht fo evah ew roloc ylno eht s’eulb ,yrroS“
,llih eht nwod uoy teem ll’I“
.daeh sih ni 32 mlasP fo etouq suomaf-reve eht gnitelpmoc
eb d’ti thguoht I …huH“
.redluohs s’orteiP gnittap ,nrut ni delims eeL
.ereht ni reve naht lufituaeb erom neve demees hcihw
.thgin gninepo ta ereht eb annog s’eh ,puY ?snaem taht tahw sseug oS
!taht tuoba gniht nuf ,haeY
.retaw emos teg og dluohs I ,yrroS“
.onihr eht dias ”,ti ekil ay tuB“
.yenom sih koot ehs sa eeL ot denrut neht eH ”.uoy knahT“
.eireganeM oirT fo tsiloiv eht dna
”,emoh a evah ot ecin s’ti sseug I“ .deddon orteiP
”,kwah kcalb nabuC“
.em dnoyeb si teef sih ta gnillaf seidal evah t’nseod eh woH
yaw eht ,htaerb yreve sih htiw devom sredluohs sih yaw eht
”.semitemos efil ytic htiw melborp eht s’tahT“
.daeh sih gnikahs ,delkcuhc orteiP  ”.elpoep
tpecxe ,tuoba kniht ot esle gnihtemos mih evig ot gniyrt ,tniop taht ta dnuorg eht otni gud snolat siH
gniliar eht gnippat
.niatruc on dah ni deyalp orteiP retaeht ehT  ----**----  orteiP-
…  …gnihtemos ro uoy rof eman a htiw pu emoc
,sdneirf ym fo elpuoc a htiw yltnecer nwot otni tnew I
.nuf eb ylbaborp ll’tI
.odeeps sih tsap nwod gnippird
”?he ,yob ytic a neeb syawlA“
!ecneirepxe wen a s’ti
.yug a s’eh ,lla fo tsom tuB
.hguoht ,tcartnoc eht ngis ot deen llits I  .onnud I
.smeti suoirav nacs ot gninnigeb erofeb
.dias eh ”,gnihton-N“ .dnim
ot tuo dna ni dehtaerb eh sa
.orteiP dias ”,thgirlA“
.seceip otni derettahs eirever ehT
”?yllanigiro ,ekiL ?yawyna ,morf uoy era erehw oS“
.gniggurhs erofeb ,tuo esac s’orteiP dexaoc yltneg neht ehS
.yltsenoh ,thgieh si ti fo tsoM“ .dias eh
.spohs gniyrav eht lla ees ot llih eht pu klaw ot deunitnoc eh dna ,ffo tfel erew yeht erehw ot
.deilper orteiP ”,teb ll’I“  ”.ereh syug uoy evah ew taht evol yllaer eW .strats nosaes eht ecno dnuora emoc ll’uoY“
.ecalp ylevol siht ot txen m’I wonk I won
.orteiP dias ”,raeh I oS“
strats tsuj traeh ym ,mih ot klat I emit yrevE
egral tif strihs egral-artxe lla ton ,ees nac uoy sA“
”.rehtie ,siht ekil sweiv ylevol evah t’nod yeht ,niaga neht tuB“
.tuo detniop eeL ”,oot ,ereh erehwyreve teg ot rac a deen aY“
.dias eh ”,esactius ym teg em tel tsael ta ,ollec eht teg ot gniog er’uoy fi ,lleW“
.deddon orteiP  ”!epoh I ,ecnamrofrep tsrif eht ta uoy ees ll’I“
.ti gnikahs dna dnah s’eeL gnikat ,delims kwah kcalb ehT  ”.streboR eeL“
,rood eht ot revo deklaw orteiP ,siht htiW
.ti ekat ll’I .ti kcuf tub ,won krowloohcs no dniheb m’I snaem tsuj taht ,esruoc fO
.notsoB ni desab naicisum dna retirw a si ohw
,yb esolc rehtar saw retaeht ehT
,yeh dnA  !esaelp ,seY
!taht ekil mih ta kool em nees evah t’ndluoc eH ?thgiR
…mih ta kool I emit yreve dna ,ruoh na selim evif ythgie ta gnicar
,mH“ .tuo trihs haimereJ eht dellup neht eH .dias orteiP
.kcab tog I ecnis citceh neeb tsuj s’tI
.tol a cisum sekil eh tuo snruT
,saw kcurt eht wenk orteiP erehw ot niatnuom eht pu gniklaw nageb neht eH
”,peY“  ”.taht esu lla dluoc ew kniht I
.hcum oot taht tuoba yrrow ot evah t’nod I dalg m’I“
dna deb sih otni gnipael erofeb srebmem surohc desufnoc wef a tsap gninnur ,ni dehsad eH
”.aera siht ni erehwyna retaw hcum siht gnitcepxe t’nsaw I ,timda I“ .dias eh
,lleW“ .delims onihr ehT ”?eh diD“
”,oddik ,’nileef eht wonk I“
”.selaroM-ittA .rM ,gnimoclew yrev eb ot sgnirpS akeruE fo elpoep eht dnif ll’uoy kniht I“
”,si ti tahw si ti ,lleW“  ”.recin
”?kcab eht ni kcots eht kcehc ay dluoc ,amliW“
ylthgils kaeb sih gnitrap
.dias eh ”,selaroM-ittA orteiP“
deppets worraps redlo rehtar A
.eeL dias ”,ecin eb tsuM“
”.ereh tuo cisum hcus raeh ot teg uoy netfo ton s’tI“
.htmraw eht ta gnilims kwah kcalb eht
.ylevissimsid dnah sih gnivaw ,daeh sih koohs orteiP
.woleb sniatnuom eht ot tuo gnikool ,deggurhs eH
.meht evoba tsuj ti demarf taht srats eht no dna
”.esle gnihtyna ro ,riah ,ruf elttil yrev dna
”,drah yrev gnikrow neeb ev’ew ,lleW“
”?erolpxe ot emit emos teg ew sseug I …semaJ ,oS“
”?haey ,mih rof ’nitoor m’I mih llet at erus eb
,oot ,ylevol saw aera ehT
”.ti ot no dleh syawla ev’yehT .tniop yna ta ni pu werg I esuoh eht fo tuo devom reven I“ .dias eh
.denedaorb elims sih dna ,esor worbeye s’onihr ehT  ”.flah a dna htnom a rof arepo yalp ot ereh ,imaiM morf drib a tsuj m’I“ .deggurhs eH .deilper eh
dna …ereht thgir eb ot teg I .yllautca ,ecin fo dnik s’tI“ .deggurhs eH
.eeL ot ffo ti gnidnah ,yldeirruh
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,airetefac eht otni kcab teg dluohs eW“
,revird eht dias ”,si ti ereh
”.siht gnitcepxe ton saw I …nmaD“
.syug otni ton m’I dnA
.etaicossa selas wollef sih ot denrut eH ”…mH“
”,haey ,thgin ylevol a s’tI“
”.retaw hserf ni ’nimmiws
.taht no desucof ton saw noitnetta rieht tub ,doots pohs euqitna na ,thgir rieht oT
”,mih rof sgniht fo ytnelp tog ev’ew erus m’I ,lleW“
.sdneirf ym fo yna htiw
mih otni gnipmub peek I .knat a ekil tliub s’eh esruoc fo dna ,onihr a s’eH .onnud I .huH …hguoht ,yug eno siht si erehT
”.liaf tuohtiw hcum ytterp ,thgin yrevE“ .orteiP dias ”,peY“
uoy ekam t’nseod tahT .yug eno ta gnikool
.nwot siht fo draeh neve t’ndah I ,onnud I ?sgnirpS akeruE .yllautca
,epols eht pu deklaw eH
”,rehtie ,ereh pu tiusmiws a gnirb t’ndid osla I ,lleW“ .delims orteiP
”.ecalp siht ot pu emac I erof‘ sraey wef a rof atnaltA ni devil I“ .dias eh
.deilper orteiP ”,oot uoY“
.knurt eht denepo ehs sa delkcuhc rodarbaL ehT
.erom taeb traeh sih edam ylno hcihw
”?yadot ay pleh I nac woH“
”.erehwyreve teg ot rac a deen uoy dnA .suoixonbO .duol
.desicrexe ylerar eh ria na saw ti taht kool eno morf detcepsus orteiP tub
”.sthgin laturb erew esohT
.sreyalp artsehcro wollef sih ot gninrut ,nwot eht dnuora decnalg orteiP
”.sthgil ytic tuohtiw ecalp a ees ot ecnahc a dah yllaer reven ev’I“ .deilper orteiP ”,ti s’taht sseug I“  .eeL deksa
.niatnuom a fo epols eht no thgir nwot llams a rof elbakramer dnuof eh hcihw ,deniatniam llew yrev lla erew yehT
”,tsillec eht tsuj
,klat tsuj at sdrawretfa emit dah ay fi ’nirednow saw I ,lleW“
,deddon neht eH  .oot lliw ew dnA
.gniddon ,revird eht ot dekool neht eH
.deggurhs eH .eeL dias
”.ereht ecin sa t’nia weiv eht ,sediS‘“
.thgir lla dneirf doog a s’eH .haeY
neht eH ”.ereh ti evol annog er’uoy erugif I“
.trihs nwo sih ta gnitniop ,delkcuhc neht eH ”…lleW“
yaw sih gnikam ylkciuq dna tip artsehcro eht fo tuo gniklaw ,denrut kwah kcalb eht ,siht htiw dnA  ”.neht uoy eeS“ .kcab delims orteiP
”,won ffo ekat tsum I diarfa m’I“
.dias eh ”,oddik ,sknahT“
.sniatnuom eht ni tca tsrif ruoY“
,thgir gnihtyreve tog onarpos ruO
.tib a ereh dnuora ecaf ruoy nees ev’I“
a m’I .sregnis eht fo eno ton m’I
.rac eht fo kcab eht ot deklaw eh sa kcapkcab sih gnibbarg ,tuo deppets
.elims a mih gnivig ,orteiP ta kcab dekool eH .deilper eeL
,naem I ?thgir ,ereh no gniog s’tahw eb t’nac taht tuB
.onihr eht ot resolc tib elttil a gnigde ,delkcuhc orteiP
,rood eht fo tuo ydaerla saw rodarbaL eht tnemmoc dluoc eh erofeb tub ,esirprus ni deknilb orteiP  ”.od
,hciwdnas sih no nwod tib neht eH
,onihr eht dias ”,emoclew dna ,olleH“
”.ylevol syawla era ereh dnuor‘ sthgiN .ti ees at ereh eb at tog ay dalg m’I ,lleW“
,kcab eht ot og ot tfel neht
.deilper onihr eht ”,llitS“
.kcab gninael ,deilper hsoJ
s’tI …ekil s’ti tuB .yaw siht gnileef m’I yhw neve ro ,si ti tahw wonk t’nod I
,snoitceffa s’eeL ot sdnopser orteiP woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.delkcuhc eH ”…hu …lleW“
,etis eht ot pu dellup elcihev ehT  ----**----  .orteiP-
,delims orteiP  ----**----  orteiP-
,neht dnA  —ton m’I
.ecalkcen nedlog a dih ylerab hcihw ,trihs yerg elpmis reh ta dekool orteiP
.draeb evisserpmi na htiw
.ydob s’onihr eht no llits ezag sih ,desuap orteiP
ti evil ot dah sah ohw enoyna ot elbazingocer yletaidemmi htob si
.deggurhs neht eH
nac I tsael eht s’tI“
,naem I :erus rof taht wonk uoY .gnihton
”!era ay ereht dna ,hA“
,kcezzoW rreH yb
tlef reve ev’I naht mih dnuora elbatrofmoc erom leef I tub ,eeL tuoba si ti tahw wonk t’nod I
,edistuo eht ot yltnenimorp deyalpsid saw taht trihs a ot pu gniklaw ,deknilb eH
,ereht tnadnetta selas rehto eno deciton eH
.srehtaef sih dezeeuqs dna daeh sih no sdnah sih decalp eh sa dnuora gnicap
.deksa eh ”?spooH“ .daeh sih detlit onihr ehT  ”?wonk uoy ,spooh toohs ot llat ytterp eb ot evah uoY
”.neht ,tib a ni uoy teem ll’I“
,kwah kcalb eht ot ti tuoba
!siht ekil ecalp a evol d’eH
”?ruoh na tuoba ni hcnul ot teerts eht pu teem ew oS“
”,eeL ,gniht eruS“
.daor eht ot kcab gnitniop
.orteiP dias ”,ereht evil ot tnaw t’nod uoy tub ,haeY“
.pu kcab thgir emac sthgil esuoh eht dna ,demmid sthgil egats eht taht erom saw ti ,esolc a ot emac ataivarT aL fo tca tsrif eht sa ,eroferehT
,eeL ot denrut orteiP ,dnoces a retfA  .eeL ot
.dnats sih no kcab wob sih tes eh dna nwod deid esualppa eht sa hcum derac yllaer orteiP taht toN  .ecalp eht nekrad ot hguone tsuj saw ti retaeht eht edisni
.lacihposolihp ytterp osla s’eH
.eb annog si nur eht yzarc woh rof pu gniraeg s’enoyreve
,sih htiw delgnim ti sa htaerb s’eeL fo erawa yltniaf saw orteiP
”.sseug I ,reppoP tsuJ …hE“
esolc pohs cigam a deciton eH .nihtiw spohs gniyrav eht lla fo kcots gnikat
.delkniwt srats eht woh ta dekool eh sa nihtiw morf etaname htmraw ddo rehtar a tlef orteiP .tniop noitaripsni fo atsiv eht ta tuo gnikool
,delims orteiP ,revewoH .esirprus thgils ni denrut htob orteiP dna hsoJ
”.gnillevart hcum did reven sklof ym ,ti fo kniht ot emoC
”?wonk uoy ,strats tca txen eht erofeb emit hcum os ylnO
”?ereht revo lewot taht em gnitteg dnim uoY“
.ereh ti evol annog er’uoy erugif I“
.dias ehs ”,thgirlA“
”.taht rof uoy knahT“
”!emac uoY“ .onihr eht ot dnah sih gnidnetxe ,dias eh ”!eeL“
.onihr eht ta gnilims ,deggurhs orteiP
wohs ot ton tseb sih did eh hcihw fo lla
DOG ESAELP GNINEPPAH EB T’NAC SIHT GNIMAERD M’I GNIMAERD GNIKCUF M’I EM LLET ESAELP LANRUOJ EHT FLAH HGUORHT DEBBATS TSUJ I KCUF GNIMAERD GNIKCUF M’I EM LLET ESAELP DOG RAED GNIMAERD M’I LAER T’NSAW TAHT DENEPPAH REVEN TAHT DENEPPAH TSUJ KCUF EHT TAHW DOG YM HO
.yzarc saw ti ,nam dnA .tih hsams a saw thgin gninepO
,naem I .tuo taht derugif eW
,yhw wonk t’nod I
.ekal eht ot tuo dekool eh sa
flesmih ot esolc sgel sih gnidloh
”.flesym tcartsid ot tpmetta na tsuj s’ti sseug I .wonk t’nod I“
.emac yeht yaw eht kcab gniog
.era uoy tahw gniwonk ton
.ydob sih revo srevoc eht gniworht
,hO“ .daeh sih koohs eH ”?egnar yM“
.ereht erew yeht erehw stnap sih teg ot ylekil tsom
”,won ti wonk ay ,lleW“
,ecnelis ni no daer kwah kcalb ehT
”?auhsoJ …er’uoy dnA“
”.yawyna ,ereh dnuora stcesni ’niggirf eht lla morf trapa ,lleW“
.elttil a drawrof deppets namselas onihr ehT
”?gnorw s’tahw ,orteiP“  ”…tsuj I“
.onihr eht ta pu gnikool ,denrut orteiP
trihs ybraen a no gninael ,deilper onihr eht
”.flesym rednow I ,semitemoS“ .flesmih mlac ot
,retniw eht ni teiuq laeR
”,tib a ezeerb eht toohs
m’I …lleW“ .deknilb orteiP  .deilper eeL
,yag ton m’I  .resolc tnael
.dias eh ”,ti ekat ll’I“
”,ysub t’nia ay nehw dnuora ay wohs nac I“
!noitnem ot dedeen I gniht eno saw erehT !hO  …zeeJ
,yrots s’yadot ni ,sselehtenon noitanalpxe na hcus tpmetta su tel tuB
.erofeb aera suoniatnuom a ot neeb reven ev’I“
.riah gnol htiw rodarbaL redlo na
,deladepkcab orteiP ”!em hcuot t’noD“
.deggurhs onihr ehT
.dedda eh ”,ereh dnuora smaj ciffart yna evah t’nod uoy dnA“
,noitanigami eht ot hguone elttil tfel tI
sih ni sdnah sih ,yawa gninrut dna mlif gnilc eht no hciwdnas dehsinifnu eht gnicalp ,denworf neht eH
,daeh sih koohs eeL
na yletamitlu si tahw fo ksa ot em fo diputs yllaer ylbaborp si siht wonk I
”!sgniht od nac ew os rebmun ym ay teg em tel nehT“
.srats eht ta gnikool elihw edistuo gnittahc
”,aigroeG ,atteiraM ’lo dooG“
.zzaj taht lla …smaxe ,stnemngissa yroeht
…woh deciton yletaidemmi kwah kcalb eht dna
.taerg era sregnis ruo
,seye sih desolc eeL
.saw dnuopmoc eht erehw ot teerts eht ssorca gnikool erofeb
.resolc mih llup eeL gnileef ,seye sih desolc eh sa ysatsce elbaraebnu na tlef eH
”.ereh morf ti ekat ll’I .uoy knahT“
tub ereht neeb syawla sah taht fleseno tuoba hturt emos fo ,noitazilaer fo tnemom ehT
,niks evah tsuj yltsom eW
”,ruf no esrow neve eb tsuM“  ”!uoy llet em tel ,srehtaef ruoy fo tuo taht naelc ot nuf ton s’tI .tuo pets uoy ecno srehtaef ruoy no gnitaropave tlas eht evah syawla uoy ,retaw tlas htiW
.hsoJ ta gnikniw ,deilper onihr eht ”,thgir taht tog aY“  ”?thgir ,eeL
”?huh ,artsehcro eht gniod er’uoy os ,hA“  ”.tsillec
.selbuort sih morf kwah kcalb nabuC elttil eht evas ot ereh
”?uoy t’nevah ,efil a etiuq dah ev’uoY“
.thguoht eh ,taht ot desunu m’I ,doG raeD
”.hguoht ,egral-artxe llits s’tI“
.ereht sllib fo elpuoc a gniyal dna tellaw sih tuo gnillup ,deddon orteiP
.tuo dna ni gnihtaerb ,daeh sih koohs eH
,meht htaeneb yltcerid skrazO sasnakrA eht fo atsiv eht no desucof saw ti ,daetsnI
”?thgin gninepo no uoy ees ll’I sseug I oS“
.taes s’revird eht ot deklaw ehs sa rodarbaL eht dias ”,emoclew er’uoY“
…ev’I“  ”?—s’tahW“ .deksa eeL
.kcod eht no yawliar a revo lewot eht gnuh eeL ,siht htiw dnA  ”.kcab eb ll’I“ .eeL dias ”,dooG“
”?tiusmiws ycnegreme na uoy teg ll’I dna emit emos nwot ot ffo nur nac ew esoppus I“
”?eno siht tuoba tahw
.em rof ’nitae at kcab s’ti neht dna ,stnap ym otni kcab teg annog m’I“ .delims neht eH
”ruoma’D ruoJ ereimerP eL“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
”.ereh tnemtaert ecin ytterp teg neve eW“
.niaga uoy ees ll’I
ytterp s’tI .oga edaced a ereh emac I ecnis retaeht eht ni ees at deganam ev’I arepo ylno eht s’tI“ .eeL dias ”,peY“  .deksa eh
”!tfil eht rof sknahT“
.yletaidemmi pu doots kwah kcalb ehT
siht saw tI .ereh dnuora strihs-T rof spohs modnar eht fo eno ni gnippots elihw mih tem yllautca I ,si gniht ynnuF
.eeL dias ”,taerG“  ”.yakO“
.ecneidua eht morf tip artsehcro eht gnidivid reirrab eht tsniaga denael eh sa onihr railimaf eht gniees
:llew sa ,pu kcab emoc ot sthgil eht rof emit gnihcaorppa saw tI
.ecin ytterp si cisum s’idreV tub ,tolp toidi na sah arepo taht kniht yam I
.dluoc eh sa drah sa yawa gnihsup erofeb ,tsehc s’eeL otno sdnah sih decalp orteiP
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.taht rof peels ym teg attoG
.erow eh trihs deralloc etihw eht ni tuo deglub selcsum s’onihr eht woh gniciton orteiP ,delims eH
.enohptrams s’eeL ta gnikool ,delims orteiP
”?rebmun rey s’tahW .rebmun rey rO“ .enohptrams sih tuo dellup neht eH
,ylkciuq taeb traeh siH
!oot ,taht rof peels teg retteb I
.nekops-tfoS .yllautca ,teiuq
…ecaf sih dna nroh sih demarf srats eht
.nwot ylevol a si ecalp sihT
”?strops fo stol syalp eh oS“
”?gnorw gnihtemos sI“  ----**----  orteiP-
.flesmih ot detnahc eh ,yag ton er’uoy
.retaw eht fo tuo flesmih gnillup dna kcod eht gnibbarg ,revo maws neht eH .devresbo eeL
.pu doots neht eH .deilper orteiP
.dnuopmoc eht fo rood eht ot evruc eht nwod gnihsur
.worraps eht dias ”,seY“
.nwot ni od ot tol a etiuq yllautca s’erehT“ .worraps eht dias ”,tnaw uoy fI“
…tub ,tcejbo etaminani
.did ehs sa retnuoc eht no gninael eeL
”.retaw eht ekil ylbaborp d’uoY
.tcepxe t’ndluow osla uoy gnihtemoS
,reyalp rehto ehT
.mih dedroffa srehtaef kcalb sih taeh fo esir thgils eht tlef ylniatrec eh dna ,mih no nwod erob nus noonretfa ylrae ehT
”.strap eseht dnuor‘ od nac ay tahw desirprus eb thgim aY
.ydob sih degguh taht trihs deralloc etihw a no dellup eh sa delims eh dna ,neht yb snaej sih otni nettog dah onihr ehT
retsaf gnitaeb
.”ereh morf trihs a etaicerppa thgim eiggA ,yeh“ gnikniht saw I dna ,yllautca ,pohs naitsirhC
.em rof sehciwdnas emos devas ay epoH
”,ti evah uoy ereht dnA“
.orteiP ta revo dekool eeL
.ylivaeh dehtaerb eH
.rae sih dekrep hsoJ
:hcum ekil kool ton did tI
dluohs I ekil leef I .driew s’tI …dna
.flesym ,won taht gnirevocsid m’I sseuG“ .deggurhs eH
eeL ta gnizag flesmih dnuof orteiP dna
esuaC‘ .thgin tsal etal repus pu saw I
.dias eh ”,eruS“  .deksa eh
syawla s’ereht dna ,ytic a ni od ot tol a s’erehT .taerg s’taht ytic a tuoba gnihtemos syawla s’erehT“ .deilper orteiP ”,dlrow eht rof pu ti evig t’ndluow I“
”.hguorht teg ot sruoh flah a dna owt uoy ekat t’nseod evird etunim-net a ,eroferehT“
5102 ,81 enuJ  ----**----
.oot ,emahs a s’tI“
”—t’nod I tub ,sknahT“
eeL taht deciton eh neht ylno saw tI
deppirt ylraen nam gnidael ruo
.rac eht fo tuo deppets neht ehS ”.tsisni I ,esaelP“
,raef ni derevihs eh
”!uoy teem ot desaelP“
,tahw sseug
”.ecalp gnikool-ecin a saw ti taht saw draeh I llA
.yzarc dna dliw saw ti …stixe sih fo eno no
”.erots ni saw tahw ees ,slasraeher neewteb tib elttil a nwot erolpxe d’I thguoht I“
.ton sah ohw enoyna ot nialpxe ot elbissopmi spahrep dna
,sgniht fo stros lla tuoba uoy ot gniklat neeb ev’I
.rehto hcae morf ffo tilps snaicisum artsehcro eerht eht ,siht htiw dnA
:meht emalb t’nac I ,lleW
ttum eht ,tnemom taht tA
.edistuo-flah dna edisni-flah ,dekool ti railucep
?doog s’ti sseug I …s’tI
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.ecaf sih fo tuo srehtaef emos gnihsurb worraps eht ,semaJ dias
.eeL tuoba yaw siht leef t’nac I .syug otni eb t’nac I oS
”!taerg ’niod lla er’eY“
”—emas eht gnikniht tsuj saw I“
.saw ollec s’orteiP erehw rac eht fo kcab eht ot gniklaw
.rodarbaL eht dias ”,era uoy ereh ,lleW“  .levarg eht no esac eht tes ehs sa rodarbaL eht ta gnikool ,deddon neht eH .thguoht eh
.ti htiw gniog tsuj dna
…dna ,mih gnissik eeL ta ,rehgih tlef eh
.llih eht fo enilcni eht no detser ti woh yb depleh ton saw hcihw ,yrotimrod egelloc dlo yllaicepse na ekil tib a dekool ti
.ti nialpxe t’nac I
”.elpoep tsom emalb
,retaeht roodtuo-flah-roodni-flah eht fo sllaw eht dnoyeb ees dluoc orteiP taht tesnus lufituaeb a decudorp ti elihw dna ,esolc a ot nward dah tca tsrif eht emit eht yb yaw sti no llew saw ksud
,egasiv sih dethgilhgih srats ehT
.dneirf a naht erom gnihtemos s’eh ekil
”,taht od ot erus eb ll’I“
taog derruf-etihw a ,ereht tsillec rehto ylno eht ot gninrut ,edis eht ot ollec sih dial yltneg eH
,”eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL“ dna
elttil a lewot eht debbarg neht eH ”.erus ,hU“ .gniknilb
”?—s’tahw ,orteiP“ .tsirw s’orteiP rof gnihcaer ,drawrof deppets onihr ehT ”.orteiP“  ”…t’nac I …I“
,daor eht otno denrut neht ehS
.erutsop sih detfihs eH ”.oot ,ecin
.gnoleb I ecalp a s’ti ekil leef I“ .delims eH