.ffo rehtraf gnidnats egaruoC dnuof dna ,dekeep
.reh fo ylhgih kniht ot egaruoC detnaw ehS
,ysae gniog eht ekam ot trapa hguone ediw werg sknurt ehT
,erutcip lufituaeb ssel a edam d’eh fI
ylprahs daeh sti detlit eiplek ehT .deksa elcariM
”?ylimaf ruoy tuoba tahW“
.noom eht htaeneb kcalb tej dna ,llits
”,elbissop ton s’tahT“
,gniohce dna prahs ,staebfooh ekil dednal sdrow ehT
”.gnol siht ereh gniyats ,nrocinu a rof evarb ytterp er’uoY“
.srehtiw sih evoba ylprahs dehcra kcen siH .yawa knirhs dna
”.gninrom eht ni roivaheb ruoy ssucsid nac eW“ .dias rehtaf reh ”,emoh emoC“
.reh morf yawa secap eerht tsael tA
”?enola evil uoY“ .dias eh
reh gnidnimer ,dewolg seye sih tub
.kcen reh tsniaga srae reh denettalf dna slirtson reh deralf elcariM
.dias eh ”,uoy gnitib tuoba gnikniht saw I“
.sehctolps elap htiw dereppep ssenkrad ykni
.eiplek naem a t’nsaw eh fi nevE
,noillats dliw a ekil
,seert eht htaeneb snref erew erehT
,emahs kcom ni daeh reh gnuh ehS
”,sevlesmeht yb evil seiplek tsoM“
”,tnuh ot redrah eb dluow tI“
.ria thgin eht tilps keirhs s’noillats A ”—os m’I“
.emit emas eht ta dnuorg eht dna mih ta kool dluoc ehs taht os
,flesreh dlot elcariM
.deksa eh ”?tae uoy oD“
,htap eht ssorca liat gnol reh dehsals ehS
”?naem uoy od tahW“
.llorts tilnoom a rof tuo regnarts yldneirf a ton
.niaga klaw ot nageb dna
,derewol eciov siH
.raef ruoy llems nac yeht dna
…fi naem I …yeht erus m’I“
.edis reh raen yrev
.wodahs dna etals ot denrut
”?eman ruoy s’tahW“ .dias eh
”.seiplek ni eveileb t’nod I“
”?swodahs morf yawa yhs snrocinu lla od rO“
.htrae eht nopu pirg reh denethgit elcariM
,raf taht reh dewollof stnerap reh fi ,wenk ehs dna
”,su fo eno rof si ti suoregnad woh wonk uoy oD“
”,oga sruoh emoh neeb evah dluohs uoY“
”,yawyna emoc evah t’ndluow I“
.revolc teews ,hserf eta ehS
,levarg eht tsniaga tuo gnar sfooH
,meht rof dehcaer sehcnarB
,eiplek eht tuoba wenk stnerap rieht fo eno neve fI
sevooh sih dellits eh nehw
,detlit ecaf gnol siH
,syawdaor dna stserof eht maor yeht ,sllaf thgin nehW
,dehsiws liat siH
”.elttil a dnuora denrut tog tsuj I“
.ekaw rieht ni stnirpfooh tcefrep fo liart a tfel yeht dna
.seramthgin eb reven dluow yeht tuB
.yldneirf sa ylraen ton
,mih drawot pets rehtona koot ehS ”.seY“ ”?uoy erA“
,tnuh t’ndid yletinifed snrocinU
,ezigolopa ot detnaw ehS
.resolc dna resolc deldduh sreogytrap eht dna
,niaga doow eht otni delevart yehT
,yks thgin eht naht rekcalb saw eH
,thgilnoom eht ni gniknird ydob
”?tuoba klat ew dluohs tahW .eruS“
.mih morf gninnur dna gninnips morf peek ot
.regnarts a emaceb
,stnerap reh retfa dettort ehs sa tuB
deltsihw dniw eht woN
.tserof eht otni toof deppets reven d’ehs dehsiw dna
.smitciv gnitcepsusnu rof gnikool
.pollag dna nips ot deraperp dna ,dexelf
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.delims ehs ,traeh reh ni tub
.eris dna mad reh htiw devil llits ehs fi nevE
,niaga edisa sriah revlis eht dessot ehs erofeb
,reh fo daeha dehsalf eH
.cinap dluow dreh elohw eht
sehcnuah reh no nups elcariM
”,gniklat s’ohw kooL“
,tsehc ediw reh edisnI
.ytrap s’araiT ta gnol oot deyats d’ehS
retaw peed ekil eciov A
”.gninword oN .gnitae oN .on tuB“
,retaw eht fo egde eht tsniaga deppal snref ehT
,taht ni tnemesuma hcum oot saw erehT ”?I t’noD“
”.thgin ta tol a tuo og t’nod ew sseug I ,lleW
sduolc laocrahc fo stfut dna srats ylrae wef a yb dettops
.thginot rehto eht naht regnad erom raf ni neeb dah
tlef ,levarg esool eht tsniaga yltneg sevooh reh decalp elcariM
,daeh sih koohs eiplek ehT ”.erehwyreve toN“
,reh ot tnecs a deirrac dniw ehT
.sehcnarb eht htaeneb ssap ot seidob
,flesreh koohs ehS .detrons elcariM
”retaW ot nrocinU a daeL“
.dias ehs ”,snrocinu ni seveileb enoyrevE“
”.ytrap a saw erehT“
.prahs seye reh dna
.kcen reh gnola htaerb toh fo tsalb a tnes dna ,tuo dehtaerb
,eye eno denepo ehS
.eb ot reh deveileb eh sa
,pmaws eht fo llems eht tub
,gniggalf liat reh dna
.swodahs dna hsurb eht morf
.redluohs reh tsniaga delriws ria mraw ,detrons eh nehW
.deddon dna degnirc elcariM ,raef flah dna
”.deb ni eb dluohs ehS“
”.ecalp eno ni seiplek fo tol a erew ereht fI“
?oot egaruoC nees nrocinu rehto eht dah ro
.ytimixorp sih leef dluoc ehs taht esolc os ydob ykni sih thguorb
.enot gnidnamed tsom s’rehtaf reh ni
.ti erongi ot gnisoohc ro noitcaer reh gniciton ton rehtie ,dedda eh
”.hO“ ”.ekoj a saw tI“
,emitthgin htiw detrilf yks ehT
,dniheb htap eht tfel d’yeht ecno
.evisneffo esle gnihtemos yas ot tuoba saw ehs erus
,hteet detniop eht ylno was ehS
,hgih daeh reh tpek ehs dna
.fo erawa t’nsaw ehs taht ekoj a dlot d’ehs fi sa
?ehs daH .ksa ot derehtob t’ndah ehs esuaceb eta eh tahw wonk t’ndid ehS
.dessarrabme ton saw ehs emit siht tub
,yaw eht dael egaruoC tel ehS
ylirrem liat sih dekcilf
.reh ssarrabme ot rae na dehctiwt sa hcum os reven
.smitciv gnitcepsusnu rof
.mhtyhr citnarf a taeb traeh reh
,detfil srae s’eiplek ehT ”.doog yreV“
,ti ni erad a tup eH
,ylsseldnuos gnidnal
.reh revo elttes drow taht tel elcariM ”.tnuH“
,yawhtap eht nwod dedaeh yehT
,tserc a ot detfil yawhtap eht sa tub
,emoh drawot yllufitud dehcram ehS .tuo dnif dna
.detcaerrevo d’ehS
,sevooh reh htaeneb snref eht gnihsams ,yawa deihs ehS
traeh yb wenk elcariM niarret ehT
.deb ni eb dluohs ehs dna ,etal saw tI
”?naem uoy od tahW-W“ .ti derepsihw eh
liat sih dehsiws egaruoC ”.wonk t’nod I“
dedlofnu seiplek fo elat eht sa
.reh ta deralg seye der sih dna
.gnitooh deltrats htiw dellif thgin ehT
,deklaw yeht elihw seert eht morf nekorb d’yehT
dne dnih reh dexaler elcariM
.sreh otni derats seye der sih dna ,dehcra kcen siH
.ot gniklat dnuos a retfa dluow yllif yna sa spets reh deggard ehs dna
nrettap yhsalps a ni sevael eht hguorht deretlif thgilnoom dna
.meht neewteb ria eht ni derevoh ti litnu tuo taht deggard eH ”?tuB“
”,lla retfa evarb os ton ebyaM“
.detloj traeh reh
.detfil daeh sih tsael ta tub
.fooh ot fooh morf gnitfihs dna daeh reh gnirewol ,degnirc elcariM
.selppad otni htob meht denrut taht
”…tuoba swonk yllaer ydobon tuB
.noitangidni fo ecnuo na nommus t’ndluoc tub
,ycnaf ylerup neeb yrots s’araiT daH
*** .terces s’eiplek eht morf yawa
.mih detsurt d’ehs naht erom raf reh detsurt d’eh dnA
.yb dekaerts seert ehT
.enots esool a revo rettiks ro giwt a kcarc dluow ehs
.retnac tnelis a otni ekorb dna
,ylerus ,reh naht redlo saw eH
.pmad dna tfos saw dnuorg eht won ylno
,mih cimim ot tseb reh did ehS
kcab ralucsum ,trohs a dah eH
,sdoow eht otni kcab gnarps elcariM
.sdrow reh otni retsum dluoc ehs sa yrevarb hcum sa tup ehs dna
.doolb sa der sa dewolg taht seye otni gnirats flesreh dnuof elcariM
.detaeper rehtom reh ”,etal yrev s’tI“
.debbe ecnedifnoc s’elcariM
.sdnop dna sekal ni evil seipleK
.saw ehs naht elbuort erom neve ni eb dluow egaruoC
.snoitcerid lla ni tserof krad eht dna ,noom eht dna ,dnop eht was ehS
,resolc denael eH
,ria eht ot eson reh detfil dna
.reh drawot deppets egaruoC
.dnuorg reh dnats ot egaruoc eht reh evag
.spil tevlev sih neewteb elbisiv tsuj
.rennab tnaifed a ni liat reh detfil dna
.dias eh ”,netfo yrev
.noom tnecserc niht a yb til
seye reh desolc elcariM ,eid ot tuoba saw ehs niatrec dna
ylduorp ti dias ehS
esroh kcalb eht ta derats ehS
.elbissop sa ylprahs sa desserp erew pets hcae fi sa
,revewoh ,dnim reh nI
daeh reh detlit elcariM
”.thgin enif a s’tI“ ”?tnaw uoy od tahW“ .delbmert noitseuq eht tub
,sdoow eht ta sdrawkcab dezag elcariM
,seye reh ssorca llef kcolerof yklis reH
.sdoow eht otni mih wollof ot naht retteb wenk ehs ,noillats yranidro na neeb d’eh fi nevE
,tserof tilnoom eht
seirots tsohg fi nevE
.lufituaeb era seipleK
.dehcnilf elcariM
.ti fo thguoht eht ta tsehc reh ni derettulf llits traeh reh
.sknab sti dekohc taht sgniht neerg eht dna retaw llits fo
,sehcnuah reh desnet elcariM
.ecafrus eht htaeneb gnikrul yad lla dneps yehT
”.eiplek a era uoY“
”?eman ruoy taht sI“
,tort a ot dewols egaruoC nehw detnioppasid tsomla saw ehS
,ytsrihtdoolb taht flesreh dednimer dna
”?ew era erehW“ …saw eh fi nevE
,dnoces a ylno detsal tI
”.em ekil enoemoS“ ”?evil ew erehw
.elbmarb ro erans tuohtiw
,mrof krad taht ni yal ecarg hcum woh
.noitcerid sih ni pets eno desae elcariM
,sgel ruof lla deneffits
.eurt yltrap gnar ylno taht eciov sih ni gnihtemos saw ereht teY
.edisdaor eht morf ekops
,sdrow s’araiT draeh dna
daeh reh dessot ehS ”?derit uoy erA“
pu dekrej daeh s’eiplek eht litnu duola ekops ehs erawanu
…ni su fo stol era erehT“ .dias elcariM
.tsixe t’ndid seniuqe gniydnu
.drawrof pets tnedifnoc a koot dna
.daeha htap eht ssorca gnivom wodahs a thguac elcariM
”.taht desseug ydaerla ev’uoy kniht I ,ma I ohw rof sA
”.erehwyreve era snrocinU“
.meht woleb dessap seniuqe eht sa dekoops sdriB
”.eno tem reven ev’I“
,edis reh ta devom egaruoC
,yltfos sevooh reh gnicalp no desucof elcariM
,reh dnuora elcric flah a deklaw eh dna
iluaP secnarF yb
meht fo eno taht wenk ehs dna
”?em tae ot gniog ton er’uoY“ .dias eh
,swodahs erofeb delbmert slaof ylnO
,eagla dna sdeer fo llems hcir eht
.regnol yna sdrow eht raeh t’ndid elcariM tub ,yltfos denoorc eciov siH
,eniuqe yranidro na ton saw eh
.ezeerb thgin eht ni tneb sdeer llaT
,niaga daeh sih detlit eH
.seiplek ni eveileb t’ndid ehS
,desuma dednuos eh ,niagA ”?ereht saW“
”.nrocinu a er’uoy dnA“  .dias elcariM
.sraef reh htoos ria llihc eht tel elcariM
.gninetaerht ssel mih edam erutseg eht tuoba gnihtemoS
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.gniklus eno eht eb dluohs ehs erus
.niaga yawa noitnetta reh erot hsalps eguh A
,dnop krad a fo thguoht ehS
.dias elcariM ”,yrros m’I“
.roivaheb reh yb desirprus yletomer ton dna ,detnioppasid oot ,das oot dekool tsuj eH
,neeb dah egaruoC erehw ot nups ehS
,reh revo derewot eh ,sdnah neetneves tA
.meht erofeb yal knab gnivruc a dna
,ecafrus sti ni yltcefrep detcelfer saw bro tahT
,noitcerid reh ni denrut daeh sih nehW
,roivaheb ro erutsop
gnisucca ton ,wol dna talf saw eciov siH .dias egaruoC
”.emoh gniog saw I .I“
.esop rof esop mih gnihctam
.niaga reh ta yltcerid dekool eh dna
.dias egaruoC ”,ereh evil I“
.dehca sedis reh litnu stiucsib elppa htiw ylleb reh deffuts llits ehs fi nevE
,detrons eH ”?ebyaM“
.ytrap s’araiT ot enog reven d’ehs dehsiw
,wol gnuh daeh siH
.raef fo ngis yna wohs ot ton
.deciovnu ynnihw rehtona dewollaws ehS
,htap levarg eht nekat reven d’ehs dehsiw ehS
.retaw ot smitciv rieht dael seipleK .nwod edispu
,ffits ,gnilbmerT ”!em tae t’noD“
,trohs deppots ehS ”…tub ,seY“
ssenkrad fo htaerb a
.iluap02%secnarf=yreuq_hcraes?php.hcraes/moc.snoitacilbuplaog//:sptth snoitacilbuP laoG morF skoob noitaN dirbyH dna
,htrae tew eht ni stnirpfooh eht derebmemer ehS
.thgilnoom dewollaws taht tlep a was ehs
”?eb uoy nac revarb hcum woH“
”retaW ot nrocinU a daeL“ saw sihT
evarb sa tsuj gnikool no
.seramthgin reh evag llits
.dehceercs lwo nA
.ynnihw dekcinap ,gnol a welb dna
”.sdoow eseht ni seiplek fo dreh elohw a saw ereht fi ,tcaer dluow sdneirf ruoy woh enigami nac uoY“
.erad taht tpecca ot diputs ylbaveilebnu ,hsiloof eb dluow tI
.gnihtyna tnaem dah ygolopa reh fi derednow ehS
ytilibarenluv sih esle ro ytinav siH
.detsiwt kcen reh
dnop eht ot kcab og ot hguone evarb eb reve d’ehs fI
,niaga mraw ,deksa elcariM
,seert eht htaeneb niarret sih ni ,woN
,hgih sdaeh rieht werht htob yehT
,peed yal dnop eht dna
stoor dah sevooh reh dedneterp
.egaruoC fo thguoht elcariM .suoregnaD
.daor eht ni hsilived mih denrut dah sraef reh ylnO
enot citamard ylrevo ,ykoops eht
.meht ta kool ot struh ti ylevol oS
,deunitnoc egaruoC
”.deklaw ew fi klat ot reisae eb dluow ti thguoht tsuj I“
.eciov taht wenk elcariM tub ,ediw slirtson htiw gnitnecs
.lamron ot kcab tsomla
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ytterp taht saw yllaer eh tub ,retteb wenk ehS
.decnad enam sih dna ,deddon eH
pu denepo tserof ehT
,daor eht fo edis eht morF
.sedis eht ot talf llef srae sih dna
,erofeb sa gnicitne sa ylraen ton tub
.thgilnoom eht ni tort a roF“
,tlah a ot dils ehs ,daetsnI
”.htap delevart ylroop yrev a no enola ,thgin ta
,rellat doots ehS
fooh hcae woh dna
seireS aitnepreS eht fo rohtua
nroh larips reh fo pit eht morf ezag sih gniggard
.thgil eht hctac ot demees taht
.ti erutcip ot deirt dna deddon elcariM
,traeh s’elcariM deppirg esnes dliw A
.regnol yna yllif a ton saw ehs dna
.dias d’eh ,suoregnad saw tI
.dias eiplek eht ”,xaleR“
.slirtson reh hguorht elahxe gnol a welb dna
edih htooms sih hcuot ot demees thgilnoom eht krad os
mih fo trap ylno eht erew taht sriah kcalb enif fo edam erew liat dna enam sih dna
”,ylenol fo dnik si tI“
”?tort a rof og ot eraC“
”.uoy fo elbisnes woH“
.gniraer-laof ot hcaorppa reltneg raf a htiw eram etaciled a ,rehtom reh dias
.tnemom a reh koot tI .dias eh ”,egaruoC“
uoy ekil enoemos wohs oT“
.nrocinu rehtona no yldneirf neeb evah dluow taht erutseg a ni reh drawot demia
,ylesicerp decalp saw
,ylisae tnew ehs ,stnirpfooh s’eiplek eht ot tpek ehs sa gnol os tub
.ti ta kcab detrons dna daeh reh dessot elcariM
,tsehc daorb reh edisnI
.yllif a ekil dnuos ot tnaw t’ndid ehS
,dehcnilf reven egaruoC tey
.sevlesmeht yb evil seiplek tsoM
,gol nellaf a depael eH
,saw eh eliga woh was elcariM
retsulb flah saw egar sih wenk ehs hguoht neve dna
,thgin taht smaerd eiplek evah dluow ehs wenk elcariM
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,iluaP secnarF yb
,era uoy ereh teY“
,tsixe ton did seiplek taht flesreh dednimer ehs ,gnilbmerT
mih ecaf ot denrut
.gniraelc ediw a ni pu werd dna
.flesreh rof dael eht nekat ,tsap deretnac evah thgim ehs
emoh reh dael dluow hcihw htap eht dna
,gninnur ton no desucof elcariM
.dnop eht morf yawa tpael dna
hcnup yenoh hcum oot deyojne d’ehS
.stiucsib psirc elppa niht dna
.nrocinu evarb a eb ot desoppus saw ehs taht derebmemer tub ”yracs“ yas ot gniog neeb d’ehS ”…taht t’nsI“
,niaga gnimraw srae reh tlef elcariM ”.hO“
,mih retfa dehsarc elcariM nehw dna
.dnuorg eht deggard liat reh erehw ecalp eht ot
”retaW ot nrocinU a daeL“   yojne esaelP  .moc.iluapsecnarf//:ptth :ta etisbew reh no
.rewsna ni deinnihw dna teef reh pu dekcik ehs dna
.pets rof pets mih gnihctam no
.enips reh gnola dehcti gnileef gnipeerc A ”.hO“
,ssenismulc reh decnuonna dnuos hcaE
,fooh kcalb yssolg a ni dedne sgel gnol sih fo hcaE
.pmur reh ot kcen reh morf evaw a ni levart erutseg eht gnittel
”.detivni t’nsaw I“
.hctiwt niks niht s’elcariM edam eton hcae dna
.denihw ehs ”,yrros m’I“
”?erew ew deirrow woh aedi yna evah uoy oD“
,erohs tnacav a revo draug doots sdeer eht dna snref ehT
.gniyolc ,yklis denrut eciov ehT
,htap gninekrad yldipar eht gnola yaw reh
.seirots tsohg rehto hcae llet ot noitseggus s’araiT ot deerga evah dluohs reven ehs taht
.elbuort hcum os ni saw ehS ”!elcariM“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ylneddus mees dlrow eht gnikam
flesti detarapes mrof ykni na
hgih daeh reh htiW
.ecnart a otni meht llul yehT
.deil ehs ”,gniyfirret yrev mees t’nod uoy taht tnaem ylno I“
.gelerof eno htiw gnipmats dna gnitrons ,dias eh
.yllaer ,hguoht emas eht t’nsaw tI
.meht dniheb dewollof elcariM
eman nwo reh saw maercs txen eht nehw rorre elbirret a edam d’ehs wenk dna dnuos eht wenk ehS
,evarb eb ot dediced d’ehs hguoht dna
,thgin ta tuo emoc ylno yehT
.mih edisgnola devom ehs ,emit sihT
s’eniuqe egnarts siht ni gninetaerht gnihton saw erehT
,deraelc noisiv reh sa tub
.seye der htiw reh ta derats dna
.retaw fo tnilg tnatsid eht rof gnikool
,ni reh knard seye der esoht dna
.retfa sthgin ynam rof dna
secap fo elpuoc yreve tub
,drawrof srae reh
”,oot ,yaw taht refas er’eW“
.levarg tilnoom no ylthgil gnippets sevooh revlis
”.snrocinu ni eveileb t’nod I“
.meht ruoved dna nword yeht neht dnA .dias eh
.nrocinu a saw ehS
,daor eht fo edis eht morf yldetcepxenu gniraeppa sih morf edisa
htap eht tsniaga fooh sih depmats rehtaf reH ”.seitrap erom oN“
,ylduorp gnidnats
.pu daeh sih dekrej egaruoC
,taerht a ton saw egaruoC eveileb ot hcum yrev detnaw ehs hguoht
.htap levarg eht morf sedirts wef a ylno meht htiw pu thguac d’ehS
.depoh d’ehs naht suoivbo erom saw raef reh taht tnih a
.dias ehs ”,ma I ,seY“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.enog dah dneirf eiplek reh erehw detseggus retaw eht fo gnilppir tfos eht ylno dna
…eta eh dna ,eiplek a saw eH
*** ”.swodahs fo diarfa ton m’I“
,drawrof erew srae siH
.gnimraw srae reh fo sedisni eht tlef elcariM
.stnirp eht ees ot seert eht otni hguone peed yaw rieht dnuof t’ndah yehT
,niaga detfihs dah eciov sih tub
.edis eno ot raef reh devohs taht egnellahc a
.seert eht neewteb dettort yehT
.ytpme saw knab eht tub
”,ytterp taht ton s’eH“
.ynnihw deifirret a esool tel dna
,etatiseh ot ton deirt
.reh gnidnilb ylevitceffe
.dne no dnats dna elkcirp ruf reh edam enot wen eht dna
giwt dna enots gnidiova
.ssap meht tel ot edisa derettiks sgniht gniylf dna gnipeerc lla dna
seniuqe rehto ot klat t’nod I“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,detaeper ehs ”,yrros m’I“
,tnedifnoc dna duorp dnuos ot tnaem ehS ”?ereht s’ohW“
gnikool… .seye der gniwolg sih otni derats dna elzzum reh detfil elcariM
.dnuorg yssom eht ni sehcnert gniraet
,eiplek eht fo thguoht ehS
.redlo hcum taht ton tub
,eiplek eht ta kcab derats ehS
, moc.iluapsecnarf//:ptth iluaP secnarF yb
.ecnad kcolerof gnol sih gnikam
eniuqe owt rof moor fo ytnelp saw ereht dna
.reh ta derewolg dna
,meht ot degnoleb tserof ehT
,noom eht ssorca delbmut sduolc eht
”.yas seirots eht ekil ton er’uoy eyaM“
deeps rof tliub sehcnuah dna
.reh dellats yrots s’araiT fo ohce eht
.thgin eht ni tnemevom sseldnuos a emaceb eh taht os
.retaw ypmaws fo tnecs eht ni knard dna slirtson reh deralf elcariM
,llits dleh ehS ”.elcariM m’I“
.srae reh dehcaer hgis yvaeh A
”?uoy t’nod ,tnuh od uoy tuB“
”.krad retfa suoregnad era sdoow ehT“
”?sgnilbis …ro stnerap ruoy htiw klat uoy t’noD“
.ecnetnes-dim deppots tsuj t’ndah ehs fi sa
.neeb dah epahs eht erehw ecalp eht ta deralg ehS
.trons gnirewsna na welb dna depmats eH ”.oN“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.dnuorg eht tsniaga sevooh rieht fo cisum eht dna
,daeh reh dessot ,deddon elcariM
,nruhc dluow sevooh reh sa tsaf sa gniretnac
.tnemevom prahs dna