.psalc sih ni tlef ti pmil ylnekcis woh gniciton
.niaga ehtaerb ot tsuj
.stseug etaminani owt eht fo
.llew os derutcip eh ekal taht fo mottob eht ta gnieb fo stnanmer tsuj erew yeht ,ebyaM
.ni-klaw eht fo tuo delbmarcs eh ,ylevisnefed desiar draobpilc sih htiW
.scinortcele dlo eht no noitartsurf sih no desucof eh
sgans ti fi og teL
.snep emos esol ot hguone delttar taht gum a htiw rehtob t'ndid dna elbat eht no ssalg eht nwod demmals eh
.seye nottub sih htiw
tnaruatser eht otni kcab nettog dah stseP
dna sliat rieht no snoitome rieht erow seninaC
,nruter ni elims kaew a mih evag auhsoJ
,knuks eht ot kcab gninruT
.emit gnorw eht ta dekool eh nehw ecnuop ot ydaer
,nepo ti raet ot taorht s’auhsoJ ta egnul ot deirt gniht eht
,durc fo eerf liat dna raer sih dettap
.yllufhsab denialpxe eh
.ssalg eht denwod eh sa thguoht eH .ti evohS
;thgin eht fo meti tsal sih detrats dna
,liat dna kcab sih pu delkcirp ruF
”!tegrof syawla uoY
.oot ti ekil dellems eh dna ruf s’eninac eht dekaos paos dna ,esaerg ,retaW
.dehsinif saw redro eht erofeb ecno neve neercs eht ffo seye sih ekat ton dluow eh taht erows eh ,dnim sih nI
,flesmih pots yllaer neve dluoc eh erofeB
.flesruoy fo dloh a teG .nam ,kcolc a tsuj s’tI
,yllacitsiretcarahcnU
mom sih htiw rac eht otni poh nivlA dehctaw eh ,oN
.mom ruoy txet dna no oG
.ecno ta lla dnim sih otni dehsalf gnigniws eb dluoc yeht nosaer elbissop yrevE
.noitavlas sih was eh ,yrotciv fo tnemom a nI
xof dna knuks eht hctac dluoc eh os dnocesillim feirb a rof neddirrevo saw
htolc kcalb eht derutcnup segadneppa eldeen nip rieht erehw ees dluoc eh ,seye sti nI
,margorp gniludehcs eht pu thguorb yletaidemmi eh
desiar worbeye nA
,swalc sti htiw niks dna ruf sih tuo pir ot gnikool
.ecafrus eht htaenrednu egrembus dna
.elzzum sti ssorca dehcterts kcalb eht lla naht suoibud erom demees
,kcurts etunim lufetaf eht erofeb hsinif ot evah t’ndid eH
,htolc dna yah fo edam saw ti hguohT
,ydaer teg ot trats ot evah d’eh wenk etoyoc eht nehW
meht neewteb evaw trohs A
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta
.depsalc swap sih htiw deggeb auhsoJ
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sucof sih gnilbuoD
.taem war eht pu detnuoc eh sa denetsil eh dna
.daeha krow fo tol a htiw enola llits saw eh ,sdrow sih ot eurT
”.kniht d’uoy sa xuaf sa t’nia ruf xuaf hsulp taht llA
.ecrof lluf ni mih ta degrahc dna ,delworg ,pu kcab
.yadot dah eh swohs-on owt eht fo
yrotnevni sih fo lla ekat saw od ot dedeen eh llA
,hctiws a fo kcilc eht htiW
,tlas fo enil eht no thgir depmots
.llah gninid eht otni tuo dereep dna rotinom ytiruces eht ot pu decnalg eh
.redro doof eht yllanif dna
,thgindim erofeb emit fo ytnelp dah eh taht wenk eH
,gniog mih tog eh nehW .etoy diputS
,dias auhsoJ ”,ti potS
.taht gniyrt potS .ytrid s’tahT
”.kcabtuo tiaw dna ,lamron ekil ,sthgil eht lla ffo nruT“
,mih dlot ev’tsum nivlA gnihtemos gnirebmemeR
,mih morf yawa nur ot deirt ti ,liat gninruT
.lausu naht depmarc erom elttil a tlef eciffo eht ylnedduS
.ti ot txen ssalg eht htiw gnola kcab elttob eht decalp eh
.sexob gniniamer eht tuo llif ot yllufniap deniarts eh dna gniknilb ton edulcni ot htao taht deterpretni dnim sih wohemoS
.dne rehto eht ta dehcatta regnol on s’kooh eht epoh ot evah uoy esuaceb
ytterp leef uoy teb I
nam deyerg a ekil desaeler riahc eciffo sih morf laeuqs A
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.nevele erofeb retrauq a llits saw ti taht gniees hgis a tuo tel eh ,enohp sih ta gnireeP
”.hguor eb annog s’tI
eton gnikat ylralucitrap
.dluoc eh sa kcab dial sa mees ot gniyrt dias auhsoJ ”,ooooooon ,on ,oN !oN“ ”—y rof no sthgil eht evael amm’I .ssob ,thgirlA“ .norpa sih didnu dna daeh sih dewob eh
.mih elzzum ot gniog m’I ,nivlA ees I emit txen eht dna
.daeh sih gnikahs
.smra sih no ruf etihw eht nwod dehsurb eh elihw etoyoc eganeet eht ta gnirewolg ksam terref kcalb sih
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih wolloF
,nehctik eht edisni gnippetS
”.nam ,kaew tsuj er’uoY
,flah ni meht neewteb ecnatsid eht dehsals knuks eht sa elahni prahs a dewolla ylno saw auhsoJ
raef sih htiw laed ot hguone erutam t’nsaw lleh sa erus nivlA
.yrotnevni eht trats ot rotaregirfer ni-klaw eht denepo eh
.thgirla eb dluow gnihtyreve ebyam neht taht flesmih dlot eh fi tub ,t’ndluoc eH
,tnemyolpme fo sraey evif sih ni pord a kcuns reven d’eH
,levon a gnidulcni stcejorp gnitirw suoirav no skrow
.kcab eht otni dellup rac a
.mih retfa gnisahc knuks eht dna
.ot sgnoleb ti ohw tuoba kniht ot emit evig t’nod dna
.sekorts gnitrofmoc gnol ni
.rac eht fo edis regnessap eht otni mih dessot dna
t’ndid eh sa gnol sa tsuJ
dna egawes eht ni elpoep ynam taht tif yllaer uoy naC
”,renroc raf eht ni ’nittis seimmud xof dna knuks ehT“
.tug ytpme sih fo mottob eht ta dnuora dehsols dna sugahpose sih nwod dellor srebmE .lrans a ni kcab dellup spil sih ,ssorc gniog seyE
.ti evom ot erots eht ni si esle eno on esuaceb elbissop ton s’tahT
erots eht otni kcab kcuns dah nivlA
.nehctik eht sdrawot kcab delbmuts terref eht
”.sruoy t’nsi tahw kcab ekat ot elab eht dnuora hcaer smra gnol ylbissopmi sih leef nac uoy
.aremac eht ta gnikool tuohtiw
.sehtolc s’elpoep gnissim fo sgar derettat
.saw ti wohemos tuB
.mih dniheb kcar a no norpa sih pu gnuh dna taes sih fo tuo doots auhsoJ
,ylevitcnitsni dnuora riahc eht gnileviwS .21:11
,enif si gnihtyreve ,ereht tuo gnihton s’erehT
.nehctik dna moor gninid eht gnitarapes srood elbuod gnigniws eerf eht hguorht deklaw eh
.sthguoht nwo sih naht rekciuq gnivom saw suoicsnocbus sih
.pu dekrow gnieb ro derit gnieb morf erew yeht fi erusnu tub
,eciffo eht edisni efaS
em tnaW .srenil hsart eht tpec‘ dehsinif s’gnihtyreve yas ot detnaw tsuJ
.kcab gnihtemos deugra eh sa ylbiduani ria eht otni tnew smra sih htoB
ecnartne kcab eht neewteb flesmih tup ot deganam d’eh ,yldiputS
taes eht otni dexaler eh ,nwod gniltteS
.tnempiuqe eciffo sulprus ytsur eht revo wolg eiree dloc a tfel
.nosaes ffo eht gnirud ysub leef ecalp eht edam seimmud dezis-efil eht taht
.lamina na ekil mih luam ot ydaer
dna shtped ykrum eht fo tuo pu ti guT
,desucof-repyh emaceb revo tnew etoyoc eht tnemele hcaE
.tnaruatser desolc eht ni
.siht fo lla fo tuo kcik a teg dluow eh tsael tA
,ssalg eht tsniaga pu ecaf ,erehT
,yawevird eht fo dne eht tA
.kcolc eht ta kool t’ndluohs eh yhw
,dereens terref eht
”?spil sti ta sehtolc rieht evael ti seod yhW
.lla ta emit ruoy eulav yllaer uoy fi rednow ot strats tsuj kcolc eht
morf edam si rehtegot ti gnidloh htolc etihw ehT
.llams os ekal a ni tsixe ylbissop ot egral oot sehctac morf tuc eriw gnihsif morf dellup era sreksihw riehT
.nekorbnu eb ot hguone eurt tub ,yppols saw tI
.tol gnikrap kcab eht otni tuo deklaw dna
.won emoh daeh ot ydaer saw eh
.taht gniod rof flesmih desruc eh
.dnoces a tsuj rof noisivelet eht ta pu kool ot flesmih dewolla tub decamirg terref ehT .kcuF .tiaw
.dap rebmun eht fo daetsni wor rebmun eht gnisu yb rehtruf deggal eH
nepo kcab eht ot rood eht gnuws nivlA
ecaf s’neet eht no gnuh elims ”yako eb lliw gnihtyreve“ ytliug A
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
tuo daer neercs eht egapbew etihw nialp a no tnof tniop 21 namoR semiT weN kcalb nI
.buc a ekil liat sih gnittep naht rehto
.thgindim erofeb tuo ti tnes eh sa gnol sa drah oot t’nsaw tahT
.sroolf eht revo gnitapissid erofeb nehctik eht otni gnillornu
,raeh ylraelc dluoc eh gnirettiks eht gnidnim toN
.tekcub pom a edisni thguac toof a htiw delbmuts dna smoorb eht otni dekconk tI
?nwot fo strikstuo eht ta denodnaba os
.mih ta kcab gnirats seye sselefil eht hguorht thgir seloh hcnup d’eh ,redrah yna erats dluoc eh fi dna
.rood ecivres gnidils eht sdrawot sdrawkcab nups terref eht dna mih sdrawot pets elgnis a koot tI
,tuo deirc eh ”!kconK !nivlA“
.mih fo tuo kcuf eht kaerf did yllaer yehT
.sregnif ruoy neewteb eriw eht hctac uoy litnu dum dna kcum eht hguorht swalc ruoy gard dna nwod hcaeR
.sselefil dna llits yltcefrep deniamer llits serugif owt taht
”?yenom gnitrats tsuj uoY“
.gnihtemos deppir erus ti dna eerf flesti pir ot emit tsal eno deirt knuks eht
.thgis ni erehwon saw liat detfil s’knuks eht ,elbisiv deniamer srae detniop s’xof eht hguohT .enO .owt ton ,oN
.sredluohs sih dexaler dna dnuownu eh ,revo
”gninroM eht rof tI evaeL“ saw sihT
.ti morf cinap fo esnes a pu gnikcip auhsoJ
,mih fo edisni wolg gnihtoos eht ot denrut noitnetta sih htiW
.ydaets etar traeh sih dna lamron ecap sih tpek eh
.ycarucca rof erac on htiw tfel saw hcum woh deye eh dna
.ylooc no ti tup dna tekcaj sih debbarg eh
.kaets fo bals deraes a ot no nwod deppolp rettub detlem
.retspmud eht pota gnittis rof dedlocs gnieb saw neet eht wenk eh yletaidemmi
...ruof ,eerht ,owt ,enO
mih dednimer eh sa egassam a htiw mih gnixaler
.gniniartser dna redlo tlef gnihtyrevE
,ti nees d’eh tsaL
.setadpu erutuf rof
.nwot eht raen erehwyna tnew yeht noitacidni on htiw selim rof nar sedisni deilleb denekcalb rieht
.mlac a otni mih dellul
delevarnu liat etihw trohs s’auhsoJ
”,gninrom eht rof ti evael tsuJ .ti kcuF“
,gnisac nrow rieht ni dehcrul snaf htoB
.mih sdrawot gniddap teiuq ylhtraenu sti raeh dluoc eh ,mih dniheB
.pac eht didnu dna rekahs tlas a fo dloh debbarg eH
,egatnavda sih ot taht gnisU
.deracs mih edam ti nehw neve ,ti raeh ot detnaw dna noitanigami s’nivlA htiw desserpmi syawla saw eh ,yllautcA
hsigguls os gnivom dna emit sih gnikat neeb d’eH
,tnemeticxe eht lla htiw neve ,yvaeh seyE
eson dna taorht sih otni etib ti gnittel
”?taht wonk uoy ,semitemos tihs elttil a er’uoY“
,tser eht ekil thgin etal rehtona tsuj saw siht taht ,thgirla eb ot gniog saw gnihtyreve mih dlot taht niarb sih fo trap ehT
ksed eht fo tsom pu koot rotinom evissam ehT
weiv aremac ni llits retspmud a sdrawot deklaw etoyoc gnuoy ehT
.mih ot txen ksed eht tsniaga dehsabanu gninael saw etoyoc eht fi sa eciov s’nivlA kcab denommus
.draug sih sa gnitca saw etoyoc rellat yllarutan eht ekil erom dekool ti dna
saw siht taht mih derussaer trap rehtonA
.noitnetta ot kcab mih deppans
.redro eht fo tser eht hsinif ot egap eht fo mottob eht ta knil a no dekcilc eh ,kram yawflah eht tA
ekil eb dluow ti
.tuhs rood eht gnimmals erofeb daeh sti ta ti gnikcuhc
.od ot dedeen eh tahw wenk eh
deirc auhsoJ ”!kcab yats-
.segnih nori tej eht morf kaerc gnilttesnu
.revo er’eW .enod si sihT
,smaes dehctits ylroop no drah oot gnigguT
mrifnoc ot flesmih dewolla eh ,ni gniviG
.trats ot emit doog a saw won tub
.won thgir srednilb rof evig dluow eh tahw ,doG
s’rehtom etoyoc eht tuo edam eh sa tsehc sih morf desaeler hgis A
.mih dniheb esolc hctal eht tel dna edisni deppets eh
”,thginot toN .esaaaeeeelP .nivlA“
,gab a otni yah eht ffuts ylitsaH .rof gnikool er’uoy elab taht dnif uoy lit‘ yrruh tsuJ
,yltfiws siht krow ot auhsoJ teg dluoc eh wenk ssob sih fI
.worromot ti hsinab ot woh mih hcaet nac etoyoc eht ebyam dna thginrevo ereht ni deppart eb ot gniog saw tI
.daol yvaeh a rednu gnizeehw
,ecaf sti no noisserpxe reporp a tuohtiw nevE
”,gninrom eht rof ti evael tsuJ .ti kcuf ,hhA“
auhsoJ morf elims a werd noitcafsitas fo esnes gums A
,sruoh rof enola eb ot gniog saw eh wenk eh nehw ,thginot nevE
,tnaruatser eht tuoba lla saremac nezod a otni tilps dna
.mih dniheb yllufyalp tuoba deggaw dna
daeh s’knuks eht no snottub etihw owt ehT
.ekam ot woh wonk s’etoyoc ylno nirg retsinis taht mih evag eh sa gnihsalf secarb
enola serugif krad owt tas aera gninid eht fo renroc kcab raf eht nI
,erusaem doog rof eldnah rood eht gnitseT
.daeh sih fo kcab eht ot wap a htiw detrats nivlA ”,yrros ,hO“
,flesmih dekcohs saw eH
.ysae ti ekaT .tihS
.nekahs gnieb hctal eht fo eldnah eht draeh eh erows eh
.mih ot railimafnu t’nsaw noitseuq fo tros sihT
,flesmih ebircsed ot esohc eh fI
er’yehT“( yas dluoc auhsoJ taht esucxe tahw rettam oN
”,uoy htiw mra ruoy ekat dnA“
.kcolc eht ta espmilg a kaens dluow eh
.ytreporp eht fo egde eht tsap gnol deklaw ev’uoy wonk uoy nehw neve ,pots reve t’nod tub
.ksed s’terref eht ta dnuora gnikool erofeb dias nivlA
20:11 daer tI .11:11 erofeb regnol hcum ton tub
.niaga lufyalp eb ot hguone doog gnileef htob
.noisicedni ni ezorf eh ,hguone tsaf pu gnirebos toN
.daeh sih gnikahs ,deffocs auhsoJ
tnorf eht sdrawot denrut eh ,nehctik eht otni kcab gnippetS
.mih ta gnigniws smra sti degdod ylworran tsuj eh
,nwo rieht no evom nac taht seimmud sa gniht hcus oN
…nehctik eht dna mih neewteb gnidnats knuks htolc llat toof xis eht gnidnim toN
htaerb peed a ekaT
.ylsselerac keew eht fo yad tsal eht gnihsur erofeb eludehcs gniniamer eht no nwod dereknuh eh
.yb ssap ti tel dna
,gnol oot ekat uoy fI
,denrut eh nehw ,hguone eruS
,ksed eht fo tenibac mottob eht sdrawot gninruT
ts-ts-ts-ts-s-s-s-s-s-S“ .epacse fo htap sih ni
.trap tsedrah eht s’enil eht
.daolkrow eht fo tsom yrrac ot meht fo owt eht decrof taht swohs-on lareves htiw ,ysub yllanoitpecxe neeb dah yadoT
.taht ekil kcen sih tsniaga gnilzzun tfos rehtar tlef dna hteet on dah ti tub
.regnol elihw elttil a rood eht ta deyats tub
meht tuoba gnihton yletulosba saw ereht dna seimmud deffuts tsuj erew yeht esuaceb enif yltcefrep saw hcihW
.thgiled s’etoyoc eht ot dias eh
.uoy morf sekat kcolc eht emit erom eht
,no ti ekat dluoc eh gniwonK
,flesmih pots dluoc eh erofeB
.senob digirf ruoy otni gnipees dloc gnitib eht tpecca dna edisni petS
,hctaw ot dnoces lanoitidda eno flesmih gniwolla ylnO
.gniog mih tog kceh sa erus eh
,draobpilc sih gnibbarG
.mra eno ylno htiw mih koops t’ndluoc ti
.niap yna ni yllautca t’nsaw eh
.nivlA ediseb gnikrap nav ylimaf depahs-dexob ylgu
.mra nwo ruoy ffo deppir dna enog ev’uoY“
.traeh gnicar sih mlac ot deirt dna rood eht tsniaga depmuls eh
,”sremotsuc rof devreser retteb era staes esohT“
,rae sih otni yaw rieht demrow
.gnikool t’nsaw eh elihw hguorht deppils eno dna
.deracs naht desufnoc erom won
.noos thgindim eb ot gniog saw ti dna ydaerla rood eht ot esolc os saw eh ,ti tuoba gnikniht
,semarf erutcip eht dna ,stnalp eht ,strac eht
edam yeht enut deltsihw dniw tniaf eht
.kcod ecivres eht pu kcol ,dnA“
eldnah sti fo dloh debbarg eH
.redro doof eht fo flah dnoces eht htiw emit sih koot eh
mih ssorc ot ton ti nraw ot fi sa kool gnirad a kcolc eht evag eH
.tixe kcab eht ot dedeecorp neht eh
.dnim sih no sllod detnuah tuohtiw ylkciuq rehtar yb welf sllib eht gnitnuoC
.ylevitcnitsni htaerb sih dleh auhsoJ
teg ot gniht tsedrah eht s’tahT
.latem parcs gnittif-lli ytsur fo edam
,ni-klaw eht morf tuo deruop gof dloc ecI
niaga efil dnuof liat s’reganeet eht
.eciffo eht fo sllaw eht tsniaga deohce draobyek yknulc duol eht morf skcilC
.nepo gnuws eciffo sih ot rood eht sa ylduol dekaeuqs auhsoJ ”!ssoB ,eyA“
.smeti gniniamer eht daol ot ti rof gnitiaw
”,ssob thgin ythgin ,syawynA“
.boj lautca sih hsinif dluoc eh erehw efil ot neercs eht thguorb esuom eht gnilggiW
.ot tnaem eh naht rehsrah elttil a dias auhsoJ
?ssalc a sessim ro krow rof wohs t’nseod enoemos nehw eciton ton dnasuoht net naht ssel fo nwot a dluoc woH
.rotinom retupmoc eht ta dekrims dna
krow sih otni kcab llup ot auhsoJ rof noitcartsid a fo hguone saw elcatceps eht gnihctaW
ni si hguoht taht od ot emit tsrow ehT
.xof eht ot txen ereht gnittis llits ti ees nac I hguone drah tniuqs I fI
.nwod mih eralg ot
raeh dluoc eh erows eh sa gnisir selkcah
.mih no kcirt detirips naem a yalp ot knuks eht nekat dna
,redluohs nwo sih no wap a tup ot dehcaer auhsoJ
dehctertstuo smra
,yrotnevni neht ,gniludehcs neht ,sreward eht gnitnuoC“ .ksed eht no llit hsac eht ot regnif sih deppat dna
.mih dniheb ti gnikcol dna roodkcab eht tuo gniklaw erofeb flesmih ot dias eh
.no gnisucof saw eh taht eno ylno saw ereht tub
.dekoops tog yltnedicca taht eno ylno eht t’nsaw eh taht gniees
.rekcilf ot detrats ti nehw dna won yreve dekcawht eb ot deen dluow dna
.mih ot kcab neht dna neercs eht ot devom noitnetta s’nivlA .tihs ,wA
dna doolb sih otni delkcirt
pit sih tuo dehtoos rehto eht elihw nwod ti dleh wap enO
taes sti fo tuo nettog dah xof eht
.gnihtyna tuoba yrrow t’ndeen eh dna noitcaerrevo na
.secnartne rieht ta sehtolc on erew ereht dna
?selim erauqs neetfif naht ssel aera na ni detcepser dna devol saw taht nosrep a edih uoy dluoc erehW
terref eht tsniaga ylelituf delggurts ti ,tuoba gniliaW
,sdnoces esoht neewteb ni dna ,egapbew hcae gnidaol emit sti koot retupmoc tneicna eht ,yletanutrofnU
.elzzum sih ot pil eht thguorb eh sa noisluver ni epahs fo tuo tneb sreksihw siH
.daetsni evitca eb dluohs uoy nehw ti evig uoy taht setunim esoht llA
,eye sih fo renroc eht ta yb gnirrulb ees dluoc eh wodahs eht gnidnim toN
—hgie ,neetneves ,neetxis ,neetxis ,neetfif...ruof
,dnoces elgnis a ,dnoces a roF
hgis gnol a tuo tel eh
.elbissop neeb evah t'ndluoc tahT
.erots eht fo renroc krad yreve llif ot seimmud erom nezod flah a redro thgim eh
,staes eht depolevne kcalb hctiP
”.pu taht kcip ot gniht ylno eht eb t’now tI
.pets taht ekat ot nezorf oot saw eh dna
hgis gnol a tuo tel auhsoJ
.worromot litnu kcab eb t’ndluow eh dna
!taht potS !won yeH“
,reilrae dias I sA“
dnoces rehtona gnikat dleif yrtne hcae ,yllacitrev neercs eht otno tuo dellor yehT
.aremac yella kcab eht morf saw ti tub
,nivlA ta kcab dereep eh
,wap ni draobpilC
,roolf eht tsniaga gnikcilc swalC
.dennuts yletelpmoc saw nomed eht taht llet dluoc auhsoJ
.moorkcab eht sdrawot ti gniggard
.liat yhsub egral sti deggans auhsoJ tub
.weiv s’aremac eht ni dnats ot tnaem saw eh erehw gnitacidni walc siH
deffuns saw efil s’rotinom eht
.tes erew sdnim rieht ecno dedaussid eb t’ndluoc yeht
.taht tuoba kniht ot gniog ton ,oN
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
,”yratinasnu
,eciffo eht sdrawot gnihsaD
.tib tseinit eht tsuj gniyaws erew srood ciffart gnigniws eht tub ,hcum t’nsaw tI
.rotinom retupmoc eht hguorht ti gnidnes fo yhs tsuj ksed eht otno draobpilc eht dessot eh
.knuks eht dna mih neewteb tlas fo enil a werd eh
,rewols gnitteg saw yllaer emiT .90:11
,)”aedi elbirret a si esuoh eht otni live gnitivnI“
.sdleif eht otni peed raf selab morf dellup si yah rieht ,edisnI“
mih revo deruop daerD
,enod tsomlA .80:11
,saw eh erehT .kcuf wA
redro eht htiw emit sih ekat daetsni dluoc eh tub
saw od dluoc ti lla ,eldnah s’rood eht psalc ot yaw on htiw tub
.elpmis ylriaf saw tI .redrO dooF
.dellik erew sthgil eht sa tsuj
.nwod flesmih looc ot ria toh tuo detnap tsuj eh os dna
,kcolc eht fo ffo dnim sih ekat ot gniyrT
,weiv ruoy sdnilb thgiliwt lit‘ gniklaw peeK
”.tser eht nioj ot nwod uoy sgard ti erofeb negyxo rof kcab ecar dna
.mottob eht morf maeB miJ fo elttob a dehctans dna
.spets lacinahcem tsaf ylbamohtafnu htiw devom ti
.noitnetta sih thguac aremac rehtona morf tnemevoM
.rood eht no gnab ylbeef
.tnaruatser eht fo llah gninid eht otni kcuns dna riahc sih morf doots eh
,meti tsal eht deretne eh nehW
,noitnetta s’auhsoJ thguac aremac eht morf tnemevoM
erots eht fo edisni mih tsuj saw tI
ton yal taht slennut niart
.relooc eht edisni derevihs yletaidemmi eh
.erots siht ni etal gniyats ytinas sih gnisol saw eh tub
,sredluohs sih revo depard sregnif s’nivlA .40:11
srepsihw dellihc s'nivlA
,skeehc sih desruoc tuo deknilb eh sraeT
.seye sih gnillor ,dias eh ”,ssob ,sknaht ,eeG“
,thguoht evah dluoc eh taht sgniht eht lla fo tuO
,norpa sih ffo gnilluP
,emit ni dednepsus eb ot demees
”gninroM eht rof tI evaeL“   :yojne esaelP
neeb evah dluoc owt eht erehw gnirednoW
,rood eht morf yawa tfihs ro neercs eht morf seye sih ekat ot tnaw t’ndid eh hguohT
.sllod detnuah morf pu pets a eb dluow ti ekil tlef erus ti tub ,gniveiler eb t’ndluohs eno tsal tahT
!ffo deppir mra eritne sti
.ssalg a otni hcni na deruop ylikahs eh
.srood gnigniws eht ot gnireep erofeb nehctik eht ni sthgil eht tuo denrut dna
.deppilf neeb dah selbat eht taht dootsrednu dna mih dnatsrednu ot demees tI ”.hguorht er’uoY
,flesmih ydaets ot gniliaF
.knird taht ot thgir on dah eh dna gnilaets saw siht mih dlot dnim sih fo kcab eht ta gnihctarcs A
.pmuj diletsum eht edam llits tI .PANS
,laer ylddo tlef ruf sti eciton did eh hguohT
.noitisop elbats erom a ot gninruter erofeb ylduol gnirettij
yreehc mih tpek taorht sih ni muh A
,detfil elims sih fo flah dna
.pu gnirebos yldipar ,detuohs auhsoJ ”!laer ton—ton er’uoY—reyeyeyeY“
.noitcif yrruf citore trohs dna ,allevon a
!eye eht ni thgir em dekop uoY !dratsab uoY“
,egassem txet eht ffo toohs ot tuo enohp sih deppilf dna deddon eH
.tuoba gnithgif htrow
.gniyrt neve ton m’I
,hO“ .srae sih denettalf dna yllacitegolopa nwod elzzum sih dekcud etoyoc eht
,neercs eht otni gnildduH
.keew eht rof dedeen eh tahw redro dna
.ti ecalper ot noisneherppa rof koot ti gnol sa deniamer ylno ti tub
.etoy dessesbo diptyrc diputS
dezilaer eh litnu spets wef a detrats dna
evom a ekam ot auhsoJ rof tiaw ot dekool ti ,sselnoisserpxE
gnidnats saw llod eht
.regnol tib elttil a tsuj
eniltuo tsethgils eht tuo ekam llits dluoc auhsoJ tey dna
.revo saw yad sih dna
.ecnesba s’etoyoc eht ta gnicniw
.hguone drah gut t’ndluoc tub ,pirg eht fo tuo teg ot lleh ekil delggurts gniht nmad ehT
reward eht desolc eh ,thgiarts pu gnittiS
.setunim owt ni redro eht fo flah dnoces eht hsinif tsuj dluoc eh yaw on saw ereht taht
.eye sih revo wap a htiw dekaeuqs auhsoJ ”!wO—
tlef selbat dna ksed nedoow eht fo srenroc deparcs nrow ehT
sthgil tnecseroulf yggoF
drah ytterp meht otni delerrab terref ehT
.tekcaj sih hctef ot aera kcab eht ot dellorts eh
gnol yletinifni tuo gard sdnoceS
”?oot ,esoht eldnah ot
.rood eht fo edis rehto eht no gnizeerb
,daeh sih tsniaga dedlof sraE
,egral saw elims sih hguohT .roolf eht sdrawot deggas liat sih dna
.etoyoc eht no kcab neht dna neercs VT eht ot dekcilf seye s’terref eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.kcolc atta erats ot evitcudorpnu tsuj s’tI“
,nwot nikpmub elttil ynit rieht ni enoyreve ekaw ot hguone duol ,redrum ydoolb demaercs terref eht hguohT
,rood eht etisoppo llaw eht no kcolc latigid eht ot gnicnalG
.meht no kcehc ot nosaer on s’ereht os
!emit eno eht ,nivlA gnikcuF
.tesolc ytilitu dekcap ylthgit a otni gniht eht gnulf eh ,lla ta troffe on tsomla htiW
,nosirp sti epacse ot gniyrt draeh eb dluoc knuks ehT
.neercs eht ot tpek seye sih htiw ylkciuq redro eht dessecorp eh
nepo ti deirp eh
.oN .11:11 .kcolc latigid eht ecaf ot denrut yllautibah dna
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.stekcos ynit hguorht sbew klis rieht dedaerht sredips fo sevih erehw ees ylraelc dluoc auhsoJ
.gnivom flesmih peek ot sruof lla no delwarc yllacitcarp eh
,kcarc duol a htiW
.eseht ekil snwot llams ni gnissim ’niog drah eb d’ti kniht d’uoY“
.elbat eht no gnicalp saw eh sllib rallod ytnewt eht no sucof ot deniarts noitnetta s’auhsoJ  etoyoC triD yb
seimmud owt eht fo eniltuo eht ta dekeep terref ehT
.hctal sti no tuhs deppans kcoldap eht was eh ,pu gnikooL
”?thgir ,edam er’yeht woh wonk uoY“
!aH“ .mih llik ot deirt tsuj ti fi neve ,ti rof dab leef ot gninnigeb saw eH
,troffe hctid tsal a sA
,rettiwT no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac t'nsi eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb ”gninroM eht rof tI evaeL“
mih ta thgir gnirats nwo sih no gnidnats
.edis sih ot ti dehsurb eh dna
.htgnerts dekcal ti ,llew...dna
.htiw knuks eht kcatta ot gnihtemos rof sedis sih ot dekool eh sa
.kool ot gniog toN
,ydob sih otni dedoolf detaehc gnieb fo esnes gnimlehwrevo nA
”.taeper no ta hgual ot mom ruoy dna em rof epat no lla ti evah ll’I ,deppandik teg uoy nehw yaw tahT“
.mih fo pot no saw dna ,daeh sti revo wap sti desiar
,kcolc eht ta kool yllautca
.elats detsat ria ehT
.VT eht ot secnalg trad tub pleh t’ndluoc auhsoJ
stceffe cilohocla s’yeksihw eht ,edisa gnignitS
,hcaorppa sthgildaeh owt eht gnihctaW
—erofeb elihw doog a dah llits eH
.mih tsiser ot ti rof ylno dluoc eh sa drah sa deggut dna
”.etal gniyats uoy rof em ta ffo dessip steg ehS
,depsag eh sa sgnul sih otni dehsur ria ycI
.ecaf knalb sti no liated yreve wes ot
.ellivrebmuC ni stoL giB eht ta sgniht meht tog yehT .yrros m’hA
,tuuuuuuB .thgif rehtona rof flesmih deidaer eh
.trohs ylgnissarrabme llef tub ,kcolc eht ta dessot eh
.htiw nigeb ot suovren os saw eh yhw tegrof ot gninnigeb saw dna doog tlef adnik eh ,yllautcA
detsisni tnaruatser eht fo srenwo ehT
.eerf emoh eb d’eh
!tniopefink ta mih dloh ot tuoba saw rebbor A
delrihw egdirf eht fo kcab eht ta snaf owT
ssob s’yob eht gnieb terref eht etipseD
,llah niam eht otni tuo saw etoyoc eht dna
,emarf rood eht tsniaga gninaeL
,raf oot elttil a enog ev’thgim eh gnicitoN
,llah gninid eht ni swodahs eht fo ffo noitnetta sih gnikaT
.evif ,ruof ,eerht ,owt ,enO
.der detum ni
.sniuqennam eht fo seniltuo tcnitsid owt eht was eh ,erehT
.sdleif eht fo egde eht sdrawot
,neet eht fo ecaf eht ni evarb eb ot gniyrt nevE
tsap tnatsid a ni gnivil saw eh ekil tlef tI
.gnitiaw ereht tuo saw eno rehto eht taht
.sllod ssa driew raluger tsuj er’yeht wonk I dna morf emac yeht erehw wonk I“
,llew ,efil ruoy fo etunim taht ti evig uoy nehW
.gniht sih ton saw rouqiL
”,’nitterf tiuQ
,yllufreehc dias nivlA
,mraw mih peek ot norpa kcalb gnol sih ylno htiW
.gnihton dehgiew swap sti tub ,stsif sti htiw ni lluks sih gninoegdulb deirt tI .esoht dekcal tub
,lward wols sih ni gniunitnoc erofeb deifiralc eh
.yllufyalp emarf rood eht no sregnif sih gnippar
.gniws rieht elttes ot rehtob t’ndid dna srood ciffart eht hguorht dehsarc eh
.edom yrots tsohg otni tog eh nehw mih revo lortnoc elttil dah eh ,mih naht redlo edaced a tsomla dna
.lward tcnitsid sih ni nivlA raeh dluoc dna
dnoces flah a deraps saw gniniamer meti yrevE
.si ti ereht ,tiaw oN
.enod llA  .tneS redrO
,psarg sti htaenrednu gnikcuD
.yalper noitom wols a ni flesmih gnihctaw saw eh ekil
.pal ni liat htiw nwod daeh
.tsal sih ton tub ,yttihs llits saw tI
,revenehw neppah dluoc sekatsim sih gnitcerroC
.ecneirepxe gniyfirret eht retfa nwod elttes ot tseb sih gniyrt ,traeh sih revo wap a decalp auhsoJ
egral saw neercs amsalp ehT
”,pu em kcip emoc ot mom txet ll’I ,thgirlA“
.llah eht tuo kool ot deen a yb derim saw pets tsrif sih ,yletaidemmI
.mih pots ot rehtruf yna sserp t’ndid eh
.won melborp s’werc gninrom s’tI
erehwemos tnew ylsuoivbo slennut ehT
.stluda lautca emos naht elbailer erom saw tneduts loohcs hgih a taht tespu ,srehto wef a ot sruoh rieht daerps eh ,gnilbmurG
.emoh og ot tnaw I esuaceb tsaf gnivom m’I
,rehto hcae ta tuo seugnot kcuts owt ehT
.neeb evah dluoc ti ,tsael tA
.ereht tuo gnihton s’erehT
retsnom gnizeehw a ekil dednuos htaeneb noitatskrow eht fo senigne tej ehT
.krow sih hsinif dna edisa seirots tsohg eht lla tup ot dedeen eh ,evael ot detnaw reve eh fi dna
,dnuos on derutpac aremac eht hguohT
.retaw eht mraw nac nus eht erof‘ ekal eht ot nwod klaw dna ylrae pu ekaW
na s’ereht ,efas erots eht gninepO
,mih htiw pu gnihctac ti leef dluoc eH
.meht ni tfel ygrene hguone llits saw ereht dna
.elzzum sih no nwod thgir emac wap s’ymmud eht erofeb tsal sih eb ot gniog yllaretil saw taht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
feiler fo hgis a tuo tel eh ,won emoh gnidaeh eb ot dalG
.thguoht lanif yttihs a tahW
.syawyna rewols og ot smees tsuj emiT
.ruoh htnevele eht fo etunim htnevele eht
.edis eht revo gnilgnad sgel sih htiw dil eht no tis ot pu deppoh dna
.ay eracs’t naem t’ndiD“ .elims dinac citegolopa ediw a evag eh sa thgil eht ni derekcilf secarb siH
taorht sih dehcnelc sregnif ynob detagnole erofeb mih sdrawot tuo gnihcterts smra ekil-hcrib etihw fo sthguohT
.sthgil eht lla nwod gnittuhs
.nalp taht rof hcum oS
.eb dluoc yeht sa dekrep sa etiuq t’nerew srae sih dna skeehc sih ta deretlaf ti
...dna debbarg terref eht tub ,ecaf eht ni mih ekirts ot wap sti desiar ti ,niagA
.flah ni tuc neeb dah boj etunim ytriht a eb yllausu d’tahW
.thgiliwt sseldne eht noitseuq t’nod dna emit eht tuob‘ yrrow t’noD
,nwod dekool knuks ehT
,tnemmoc eht yb dedneffo fi sA
htaenrednu sgab dah seye s’yob etoyoc ehT
knird eht esahc ot esu dluoc eh taht eciffo eht ni gnihton saw erehT
.feilebsid ni htrof dna kcab koohs eh
,gnivom dna desucof flesmih peek ot gniyrT
.emarf esool eht tsniaga gniknalc ,ylision
.seye denottub eht hguorht klis rieht daerht sredipS
.revotfel retrauq a dah ylno ti won tub ,lluf tsomla neeb d’ti
.t’nsaw ti ,tpecxE
,ecno slennut eht nees dah auhsoJ
.rood desolc yllacitamotua efas eht gnilaes tlobdaed eht fo hcnurc lacinahcem eht rof flesmih gniraperp ,edisni yenom eht deppils eH
.ydob llits sih revo nwod dial gnieb tlahpsa ekil
.nac I won os ,evom t’ndid yehT
,ria mraw fo htaerb tsal eno gnikaT
lla mraw gnileeF
koot eh taht noitca yrevE
.yldab taht mih deracs seirots sih taht kniht nivlA gnittel dab leef ot gninnigeb saw auhsoJ
.llah gninid eht ot rood eht pu denepo eh sa
.dne rehto eht ta kooh eht hctac uoy litnu llup
.riahc eciffo ykaeuqs eht otni gniklus erofeb
.swap sih htaeneb kaew dna depraw
.egap eht llif ot tsal eht neewteb
,shtoob eht ,serutxif eht ,sriahc eht
,rae sih yb egabrag eht ffo nivlA deggard ehs ,nepo rood reh gnikciK .ekatsim giB
,gnillup dna gnilggirw nageb tI
,swap htob htiw mih no deliaw retsnom suoiciv ehT
tuo noziroh eht wollof’t evah uoy ,tesnus eht sdrawot ’nitratS“