”,kaeps nam yna teL“
emit ot emit morf tub ,saw ti eraR“
”?was uoy yrolg eht si sa hcum sa tsuj
.suoirolg erom si eh meht fo hcae nI
yas ot deganam god eht lla saw ”-deraef I“
,mih htiw delias ohw nam yna tuB
od yademos dluow yeht sdeed eht fo trap emos
,ylwols ,deddon elcaro ehT
tonnac I taht ton erew ti fi
,stsyhtema htiw teS
floWcaM boR yb
,smra s’rehtohcae ni tneps elcaro eht dna etarip eht emit eht lla rof tuB .desimorp sa
”.emoclew ot yoj a si ti mohw
”?nigeb deb ym ot uoy thguorb taht yenruoj eht did erehW
erocs a no tsew evird ti hctaw ot ,ffulb hgih eht ot tnew uzlaT ,srekaerb eht dessap dna
,thgin hcaE .mih devol
!evael ot hsiw on sah eh“
tuh eht ni erom on tpels eh dnA
”.em ton ,mih tuoba si
,tnemhsinab sih fo elat eht meht dlot dna
,eenk eno ot tnew sexanauO ”,dlot saw I .liaH“
ksam eht ffo koot eh nehw no yad taht morf hguoht
.ereht ton saw eh ecnis
,dlrowrednu eht fo ydal eht dna
noitnem yna morf yawa deihs dna
,hguone nialp saw tahw ylnialp ees dluoc
thguoht evah dluow uoy
.ylefas devirra yeht ,sey roF
,aes eht no yrotciv dna rednulp
”.hcum oot eb ti fi neppah yam tahw ,nees evah I
erehwyna I ma meht fo enon
.evah ot erad thgim slatrom sa
,rof deksanu seisehporp meht reviled
,lausu naht rethgil saw moor ehT
,uoy sevael eh ,htap eno eht nO“
,niaga ecno oreh sih dnuof dna saes eht ssorca deyenruoj
,sessik fo ecnadnuba taerg a htiw
,eciov sih fo tuo enihw a peek ton dluoc god ehT
”?ediced mih tel dna
ohw ’edistuo esoht‘
ksa ot naht retteb nwonk evah dluow ohw
.mih tegrof reven lliw I
sregnad ecaf thgim yeht meht denraw eH
.meht niatnoc ot deganam
llah eht ta kool detsugsid a tohs uzlaT ”,tnelis syats
.llew eb lliw lla“
”,eeserof I tahw uoy llet llahs I neht
,uzlaT dellum ”,seod eh fi tuB“
,uoy dessim I sa yleros sa s’ti tcepsus I“ dias dna
,mih evag noil sih ssik yreve denruter uzlaT
.on neeb dah rewsna eht emit hcaE
,dnalniam eht no elpmet a ta denrael I
wap ni wap gniyl ,sih dna
”?uoy eb etyloca taht lliW“
.ylteiuq ,deksa eh
.won seman esoht fo enon uoy llet nac I ,on ,salA
,elbats dna
.ecitnerppa ruoy ylno
,mih stiawa regnad emos fI“
.ti edistuo eb ot
,sniatnuom detnuah hguorht tseuq a no
etaf taht seirrow etipsed
,deb eht no gnittis noil eht deilper
sksam eht nihtiw fles yht lla esoL
.dedeen ton erew sgniht hcus
,yrautcnas erucsbo na tuo thguos I
.ton ti wenk eh hguoht elcaro eht
nwonk edam eb lliw tI“ derepsihw ohw
tnelitsep os gnihtyna gnirb ot kniht dluow wef erehw ,sdog nwonknu ot
,devoleb sih tuohtiW
,thgir erew sngis dna emit eht nehw taht dias evah emos dnA
,denwoner erom on saw
,pal s’uzlaT ni yal daeh siH
sksam tahw daer nac
nrael ot tuoba era yeht tuB
.em snaeM“ .dias uzlaT
”?neht ,emoclew ma I ,hO“
,dlog ni tes stsyhtema fo gnir a htiw
ecalptekram eht ni gnignis dna gnicnad
,niaga smra sih ni saw noil eht nehw nehT .mih tnuah dluow
,dias evah dluow namutsiH ”,nehT“
.egayov drah a saw ti ,sey dnA
,yllausac ,ylteiuq
”.dal ,tsrif tsaf ruoy kaerB“ .gnittis neeb evah dluow flow dlo eht erehw ta delwocs uzlaT ”.elcaro na tlusnoc yeht“ ,dehgis evah dluow namutsiH ”,tnetrop lli fo smaerd yb delbuort era nem rehto nehW“
.seno cifirroh dna suortsnom ro
”?sraew etaf sksam eht daer‘
,deisehporp evah dluow namutsiH tahw raeh ot tfig eht dah ohw
nekops reven dah eh mohw ot namow a fi
.part a stcepxe ohw
,mih htiw yppah ma I
evael ot hcihw dna
,ti dehcaer eh nehw tuB
,mih delzzun noil eht
”!was I tahw eesnu
.nettogrof saw ti litnu
?smaerd ruoy ni raef uoy erutuf mirg tahw ,tsael ta
”?yas uoy thgim neht tahw
,tsum I tahw od derad I emit tsrif eht eb ton eb dluow ti tub
?ton ti si ,modgnik sih fo gnik lufthgir a evirped ot gniht tsujnu na si tI
,ti fo retteb
nam a fo ecaf eht erow uzlaT
elcaro eht sa gnol sa
selcsum eht revo dellor ruf eht yaw eht ho dna
detas setiteppa lla
”?ekam ot eciohc sih ton taht sI“ ”.dnuof eb ot
egrab a nopu emoc dah yehT
s’uzlaT ]a[,meht derewsna dah eh retfa
,niaga uzlaT dessik sexanauO—
”?siht neeserof evah uoY“ ”.em truh ot ton
.ti fo yna rof naeb a derac meht fo rehtien
.dloterof evah uoy sa si lla dna
,dias evah dluow namutsiH
.llah eht otni edorts dna
.yrtnuoc ruoy tuoba em llet ot uoy ksa dluow I“
stsyhtema fo gnirliat a deedni saw ereht dnA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
elsI tircO fo elcarO eht dna
.yawrood eht hguorht deppets eh sa ezorf god ehT
”,erofeb neppah ot ti nwonk reven evah I“
,wollof lliw ohw esoht dael lliw I neht dna“ ,sexanauO dias
.ti dethgis eh erofeb sruoh
?ti fo ksam eht ni
,dedeen yletarepsed os erew seimra eseht esuaceB
,derahs meht fo ynam hcihw
,mih erofeb ynitsed suoirolg a dah eh ,eya dnA
,noil sih htiw retniw eht dneps ot tnaem eh erehw egattoc eht tsap
,gnihton htrow sa neeb evah thgim
elpoep hsiloof dna egnarts emos“
”,elbapacseni htaed neve ro
.yrautcnas eht dna sthgieh eht drawot tserof eht otni dna
,denepeed lwocs s’uzlaT
,dnalemoh sih fo meht ot ekops eH
”.tsew secaf ti tub“ ,dloc werg
”,uoy denommus sah elcaro ehT“
:seirc dna ,gnik dercas reh niaga nworc oT
etyloca na neeb dah ereht fI
,ta derednow eb ot yldrah si hcihW
,sgurd ro reizarb ro ksam tuohtiw
,esirnus eht erofeb ekawa saw uzlaT
.reraelc sworg maerd yrevE“
,edit eht ekil edecer dluow yeht
,erid erew smrots ehT
.sseccus tnaillirb a neeb dah ,deedni ,diar ehT
,yks thgin eht fo neeuq eht ot detacided syad yloh eht no sedarap lavitsef eht dna
gniht detacilpmoc erom a si etaf taht
retawgnirps ni delooc snolem gnitae fO
niw ot tpmetta na ni—
,desoppus eh ,llew eb dluow tI .enola ylrettu
,nekat dah etarip eht egattoc kcirb dehsawetihw eht ni
rodnelps ni s’rehtaf reh enohstuo taht
,si eh ton ro rehtehw ,lleW“
,thgin hcae ,klaw regnol a erew ti hguohT
mrif erew topsed lacol a rof ecalp deifitrof a dennalp eh hcihw no llih eht fi ksa ot emac tcetihcra na ,thgintrof txen eht revO
.kcab rieht denrut elcaro ehT
,efil ni nrow dah eh ksam eht yb doots evah dluow namutsiH ”,hsiw uoy fI“
,srewot sselpot eht fo
,niaga flesmih derehtag sexanauO ,yllaniF
,deedni ,draeh evah I“
worp reppoc dehsinrub eht dettops llih nretnal eht no stuokool ehT
,seinitsed elbon dna
dereffo evah dluoc enoemos—
,sebor s’elcaro eht htaeneb elbisiv
,yal tsal ta yeht nehW
.dne eht ni reh ekorb ti tub—
.elcarO eb ton dluow uoy neht tuB‘ ,ekil gnihtemos dias evah dluow namutsiH depoh uzlaT dnA ”.ni trofmoc ekat ot ,smra ruoy dna
,flesmih rof ecalp elbatrofmoc a elsI tircO ekam ot hguone htlaew thguorb evah lliw eH
detinuer gnieb roF
,semulov txen eht ni krow sih rof kool ot erus eB
.erom on thgiew eht raeb dluoc luos reH
smrots fo nosaes eht dna
”nwO siH fo etaF oN evaH neM ot etaF htekaepS taht miH teL“
,otni mih neeserof dah uzlaT oreh eht ekil
,steop fo seil lla si taht dias evaH
,neddih lla secaf rieht
,ti htiw semoc taht lla dna
,debor dna deksam
”?meht yfed ot eunitnoc I fi ,sih no ro
.yrautcnas eht dniheb tuh eht ot meht nruter
.erohs eht no nem sih derehtag gniK etariP eht ,gninrom eht nI
”.nruter ot mih rof gnitiaw ,emosiraew eb lliw ti tuB“ .uzlaT dias ”,eyA“ ”.demrah eb ton lliw eh“ ,mih derussaer evah dluow namutsiH ”,flesruoy dias uoY“ .tesnus eht
,ytud sih ta deniamer uzlaT yas yehT
,deddon evah dluow namutsiH
:setaf eht yb slatrom rof nevow sevil eht fo yaw eht si hcus roF
ediced lliw eh esuaceb
yhtlaeh evil dluow nerdlihcdnarg nrob-eb-ot-tey reh taht os
”!I si ti ,erom hcum eb deedni nac eh swonk nam yna fi ,sdog eht yb dna
.dias uzlaT ”,eb yam tahT“
srae sih ni taebtraeh nwo sih raeh dluoc uzlaT ”.noitseuq ruoy
,rof uoy htiw regnil edahs ym seod tahW
smrots fo nosaes eht ,dias dah eh sa
.srettam tnatropmi erom ot dednetta eugnot s’sexanauO elihw
,snenil denrettap enif ,revlis ,dlog
dias uoy tahw fo deterpretni eb nac taht lla yhw si tahT
.elbatalap erom elat eht ekam ot
elcaro na neve naht
.delf si ,etag s’nahpro eht fo tuo dereej ,dnA
”.yas tsum yeht gnihtemos si ereht yas yeht“
yas dna ,mra ni mra dna
”,dias eb reven ti teL“
!snruter reven dna ecalp siht sevael eh fi mih stiawa taht—nwoner s’oreh a dna ,hpmuirt ,enorht—
,sdeed elbon dna ynitsed fo sraey ynam sa devil yeht ereht dna
.ti no kramer derad enon
.syaw etarapes rieht og emos tub
meht fo edistuo esoht tub enon tuB
,dehgis evah dluow namutsiH ”,esoppus I“
”’.srehtorb neeb evah tsum yeht‘
”.emit nwo s’elcarO eht ni
.mih ni raef elttil saw ereht tuB ”.truhnu dna efas
”?nam dlo ,gniod ma I tahw ton taht sI
,nedrag eht otni mih wollof ot uzlaT rof derutseg eh sa
”.mih rof dednetni setaf eht tahw eb yam taht ,eya dnA
.ereht yrolg sdnif eh
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
yltsuj htob delur dna ,denworc saw dna
:od dluow elcaro taerg a sa od ot nrut dna
,slewej dna ecips fo sograc kcab raeb ot naem won dna
”?dnatsrednu uoy ekam ot
ograc elohw eht nekat dah yeht dna
,mih llet ton od I sa gnol sa teY“
,secips dna esnecni
”?elcarO eht fo yrautcnas eht ta tseirp fo rennam emos era uoy“ ,dias sexanauO
saw erehT .debircsed neeb sah sa hcum dessap sraey eerht txen ehT
.tserof ytpme eht ta kcab lwoh ot setag yrautcnas eht ni leeh sih no denrut uzlaT
,elcaro eht ot dekool lla
,sraet sih yrd dna
.rehtorb s’rehtom sih yb ,htuoy a sa
,yrrat uoy od yhW“
fo uoy ekam tahw“
,floWcaM boR yb
,em htiw yppah si eH
daetsni gnillewd sih edam eh
,mih nopu saw noil eht erofeb
?ecalp eht rof eh dah esu tahw
”?snruter eh erofeb gnihton ot yawa etsaw uoy fi kniht etarip ruoy lliw tahW“
”?si ti tahw em nraw tonnac uoY“
”dal ,gniod era uoy tahw dnatsrednu I“
,nees dah tneduts sih tahw
”?naem taht did tahW“ .flesmih tub
”,etaf sih fo erom was uoy dias ton evah uoY“
uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
htron eht fo serohs nwonknu eht morf
”.eb nac sa noos sA“ ”?nehW“ .uzlaT dias
sexanauO llet ot
,slatep elppa revlis fo srewohs rednu ,gniciojer dima
,erutcel otni ylisae dexaler evah dluow namutsiH
,tlah a ot dewols eh fi dna
.demrofrep neeb dah setir on
,eseht fo hcihw uoy llet tonnac I tuB
.nruter eht no trofmoc dna evol saw ereht dna
,won yb gnilrans neeb evah dluow namutsiH
sredluohs s’god eht dnuora mra na tup ylno evah dluow
.refni ot tluciffid ton erew sgnileef sih os
,shtab cilbup gnimaets dna mraw eht fo
:uoy llet tsum I taht ,sala ,saw ti oS   .nekopsnu
,pihs s’sexanauO morf yawa nrut ton did uzlaT ”?uoy od tub“
.esolc mih dleh dna
”.nwo sih fo etaf on evah
.seimra reh fo pihsylla eht
.elpoep elohw a no
.secalp hgih eht no selpmet eht dna
.rood eht rof edam dna
,yrots trohs tseb rof drawA yraretiL OEL a fo renniw ,floWcaM boR yb ”nwO siH fo etaF oN evaH neM ot etaF htekaepS taht miH teL“
sdniw eht fo dog emos tub
nam a era uoy taht osla s’ti tuB“
”?enola dna elohw naht
.mih deppots uzlaT
,sgninigami ruoy ni
.dettimda saw noil eht nehw
”.devirra eh ere ,elcaro eht tub gnihton gnimoceb saw I sa emas ehT
traeh rof nworc edarT“
ni dnA
”…I“ .yltsenrae yrev
,god gnuoy eht ta gnikool tuohtiw uzlaT ta regnif a detniop evah dluow eH
,egattoc dehsawetihw a ni
egattoc dehsawetihw eht morf snoissessop yldlrow sih lla eveirter ot
.ssenregae tuohtiw saw ti emit siht tuB
gniK etariP eht sexanauO revol sih dna
wonk ot gnitnaw emac loof gnuoy kcisevol a dna ,suorepsorp dna
.slias norffas dna
.ylgnorw neesrof ton evah uoy“
gnimlaceb remmus eht derehtaew evah
drawot meht yrrac ot dniw eht thguac lias eht litnu srao xis dna
ti ni sbreh teews dna sniarg dewets eht sa
dootsrednu hcae yehT
senob ruoy no kool
,pans emitemos dluow ehs ,drapoel a
”,dal ,gnidaer ylekil A“
?mih htiw ton era uoy thgin yreve peels luftser morf uoy speek tahW
won yb ,hcum diap dah eh tlef deedni uzlaT dna—
.ksam s’elcaro eht dniheb tfeL
,wonk dluoc I tahT
,smra s’rehtona eno ni
.semit relpmis erew esoht tub
.hturt eht si ,yna fi
,mih erofeb serutuf owt eht yal uoy fI“
erutinruf elbatrofmoc dna hcir fo rennam lla dedaolnu yehT
.dias evah dluow namutsiH
,robrah eht evoba ffulb hgih eht ot gniyarts morf seye sih peek ton dluoc eh dna ”,eya rof
,dne eht nI ”.deedni
,denworc dna debor ,sexanauO fo demaerd eh ,tsrif ehT
,deksa sexanauO
,srae s’noil eht dekorts uzlaT ”,erew I fI“
.meht htiw neeb evah tsum
.noitaterpretni na
tekram eht ot ton tnew eh
.evarg dna suoituac nworg evah dluow eciov s’namutsiH ”,eyA“
,worp eht no gnidnats saw sexanauO
,yas yeht ,uzlaT tuB
.aes eht no teem yeht selpoep eht raef ot denrael evah lliw yeht
,meht gnoma eno neeb dah uoy fi ksa ot erew I fI
,namow tsugua dna dlo na ,rehcaet ym
.pil sih tib uzlaT ”.eguled a ekil
,deb eht no uzlaT ediseb pu devom
,bmot nettogrof ruoy revocsid yam
,og sexanauO tel I fi
.ycrem htiw dna
.gnieb fo demaerd erofeb reve dah yeht naht
,pihs eht rof deraps neeb dah sroirraw on
,robrah eht otni werd pihs s’sexanauO ,woleb dnA
,uzlaT rof dlog ni tes
.luficrem dna tsuj htob stcidrev reviled ot ecalp hgih a ni detaes
,sredluohs sih tes uzlaT did suhT ’.I naht
.rehtegot efil siht traped
,doots dah eh erehw
”?mih morf siht peek ot
,lamina denethgirf a yawa eltrats ot ton ot gniyrt fi sa ,ylevitatnet
,thgis teewsrettib dna suoicerp a saw
,tsae dna htron tnew hcihw spihs esohT
’,elixe‘ ro ’dehsinab‘ sdrow eht desu tfo yeht
”nwO siH fo etaF oN evaH neM ot etaF htekaepS taht miH teL“yojne esaelP
,luftsiw dna wol werg eciov sih fi dnA
.rotatcepS esirnuS eht
.ereh tiaw tsum uoY“
,dednah ytpme—denruter sexanauO nehw
enodnu dna detaesnu si elcnu yhT
?nam a rof llac ot elcarO eht rof“
,deb ruoy evah llits dluow I
meht nopu tub lla saw lias tes ylefas dluoc enon nehw
,stiaw sseddog ehT
,yas ot ycehporp hcihw gnisoohc yb
,dal ,uoy si ti dnA“
,emoc dluow yeht nehW .seoreh htiw
,hcrot dercas a gniraeb sexanauO fo demaerd eh ,txen eht nI
”!evael ot gniog saw eh was I“
derebmemer eb ot enots ni dehcte eb dluow seman rieht
.neeserof ecno dah
hsilpmocca ot gniod elttil on nekat dah hcihw—
,desimorp gnol ,ecnirp rieht sa
.kcab dloh ot htgnerts eht ton dah ehs taht
.SFHF eht morf elbaliava osla
.eritne noitseuq rieht kaeps neve ton dluoc yeht emit eht saw ynaM
wonk ot dedeen uoy tahw tub
.sterces evah ot rehto eht rof saw ti tahw
,elcarO sa syad sih fo tser eht dessap
,erohs eht no ,god sih ot lleweraf dib sexanauO
taerg htiw esohT
?setaf eht fo tahw dnA“ .enirhs evocla na ni edisa tes ksam eht
,nehT .deddon eh sa
meht htiw erew sdog eht fi dna
,ytic sih otni deretne sexanauO ,deedni sey dnA
,ecno naht erom kaeps ot neddibrof s’ti wonk I“ .deppots eh
.sthguoht sih derehtag
.ton dias evah srehto tuB
,uzlaT ediseb tas evah dluoc eh fi
ecnirp tnesba eht fo ekops klof nehw woh ro
enog saw sexanauO nehw
.gnol yrev tiaw ot dah ton dah eH
”?erom ecno tsael ta uoy was I erofeb“
.ksam suomrone eht htiw luferac eb ot dah yeht fi sa
elcarO eht uzlaT ,emit tsaL
.robrah eht evoba ecalp hgih a ta ,reve sa
”.su snaem taht esoppus I“
dna loof on saw ohw ,sexanauO oS
,ogniD mailliW yb uoy rof daer
slewej fo rennam lla dna
,enorht sih mialcer did eh dna
.eeht netaerht erom on nac yrehcaert siH
dnalsi tnatsid a fo elcaro eht sa tsuJ
,emit a rof tiaw ot degilbo saw esruocsid ereH
setyloca ehT ”.ti raews I
.derudne esuoh sih sa gnol sa rof
”.em dessim evah uoy taht
ecalp siht ot dettimda eb ot diap dah eh taht dnoyeb
.regnif a dial dah setaf eht mohw no eno emoc dluow ereht
”,kcab uoy gnirb lliw I“ .ycarip rof
,denruter pihs eht yad ehT
,dehctaw uzlaT erehw
su ot emoh a neeb sah tircO“
”,ton ti si ,nommocnu si tI“
,sraet sih tsniaga tuhs seye sih dezeeuqs god ehT .daed saw eH
,reporp yrautcnas eht otni detaerter uzlaT
detcepxe-eb-ot eht sa llew sa—
,detelpmoc ees tsum I gniht tsal eht si uoy
lias tes nem etarepsed dna sloof ylno erehw
,swollef suoiretsym fo rebmun a“
,ecalap a saw taht ytic eritne na fo god eht dlot dna
,dnal ekam ot pihs eht rof gnitiaw tuohtiw erohsa maws dna ffo evod eh tub
.og meht fo yna dnammoc ton dluow eH
:teerts eht ni tem ohw snezitic owt dluow sa
detuohs eh tahw rof tnatsid oot saw eH .drawrof gninael
,nam eht erofeb tes evah setaf eht htap a ton taht sI ?oot
,meht htiw thgiserof ruoy fo hcum gnikat ,edaf rehtie
.dnalsi eht tfel god eht
.ereht htiw edart ot dnif dluoc yeht sdrolraw damon revetahw dna
.elbmert ksam s’elcaro eht nees evah thgim
.ezeerb eht nopu tsac slatep elppa revlis fo srewohs rednu
,syad sih lla uoy htiw sniamer eh ,rehto eht nO
,rehtohcae htiw elgnat yeht ,tcesretni yeht
.tnemrot a erew smaerd
,erofeb thgin eht ,elcarO eht detisiv dah werc sih gnoma eerhT
.sseug ot drah ti edam uoy evah rehtien tuB“
emoc saw nosaes eht oS
”.tuo meht kees ohw smirglip sit yllausU
,retniw eht dneps ot tnaem dah eh hcihw ni
,esoohc tsum taht
,yrautcnas eht dehcaer yeht nehW ”.yaw eht dael“
.liat ruoy rof gnir dlog a“
.ylper ot nekahs oot neeb evah dluow namutsiH
,daeh ym no dnes yeht lliw seugalp tahW
,kcab dehcnilf noil ehT
.demialcnu nworc yht dna
,tilnu erew sreizarb ehT
esolc yrev gnivresbo enoemoS .niaga ti desolc
,ynomerec tuohtiw ,scitamard tuohtiw
teem yeht od reven dna
,smla lanoitidda emos rof spahrep neht
namutsiH ”,yad eno dnA
,od ti seod doog tahw“
”,rehtar dluow I“ ”.ebyam
,ytpme stis esuoh yhT
,ekops elcaro ehT
,sreizarb eht ni denrub sbreh dercas on
”.tsaf ruoy gnikaerb rof ecalp roop a si siht dna“
,yadot ,demees ti tuB
”.ti laever ot ton shtao dercas yb dnuob eb dluow I“
”,dal ,uoy deliaf sah peelS“
gniksa emac hcrairtam hcir a
dog yrgna na fo esruc eht esaeppa dna
,dias eh ”,reve uoy diD“
yeht ere ,etelpmoc ees tsum yeht
elcarO retaerg a era uoy dnA
,ti no wap eno
,mih fo eeserof si od nac I lla fI“
tsixe reven lliw taht gniht a sa
,esoohc uoy tahw si mih gnipeek fi tub
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?deksa erew uoy tahw naht erom wonk“
.retsaf edorts uzlaT
.trapa meht raet dluow ysehporp dna
dnalsi eht lla fo weiv lluf ni devol eh eno ssik ot nam rof
kciht si dnal taht dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
.ton ti denoitnem uzlaT neht
,denrut sah nosaes ehT .os ro htnom a
.kcurts neeb dah eh fi sa
,deksa yllautca yeht reveostahw dnA
,spotfoor eht lla no dna
,thgindim retfa saw ti hguoht pmal a htiw ekawa
.tnew I nehw ecneidua ym dednetta ohw
,rehtruf llits uoy emoclew I tsuM“
,uoy ot emac eH .eh ton
enorht eht ekat ot elixe morf denruter
.tfel tircO fo srednalsi eht fo emos dna ,deyats emos
latem netaeb sa htooms sa aes no ,yletats
,delttes ylippah erew
,oreh a sa reverof drager dluow eh
”?ereh tey era uoY“
:siht yas dluow I
sradec eht hguorht nwod htap eht deklaw uzlaT
,nrecnoc lla ecaf sih
neeuq roirraw a rof dnuob
robrah eht ta gnitiaw nwod dna
.niarts eht rednu spans dnim ruoy litnu worg yeht ro
,yad siht ot htrae eht rednaw htob yeht yas srehto llits dnA
,erauqs tekram eht ni llirg eht morf toh sreweks taem dna
elpmet denodnaba na ta serif ratla eht thgiler ot
,etaf lleterof ot redro nI
,daehrevo saw noom oN
.meht neewteb tsevrah eht fo gnik dercas eht dna
ynitsed suoirolg dna dnarg eht was I“
.daeh sih koohs god ehT
,erutuf eht esoohc oT
fo trap a ,kniht I ,emaceb tI
yrolg reveostahw tnuoc ot dalg eb d’I dna
?niamer tey thgim
,smra s'rehtohcae ni
,syad eseht ni ,gnikcohs yrev thguoht eb spahrep dluow tI
,fles ruoy kcab em gnirb uoy“
,noitarbelec ni ylluf
.deid ton dah uoy dluow I“
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb
,retniw ot hgin saw ti rof—
”.syad rieht fo tser eht tuo evil ot
.yrautcnas eht dniheb
,ydaerla em rof tnemhsinab saw ti wenk I rof
”,og dluow I thguoht uoY“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT.elcaro on ma I
.sdruc dna leurg sih nwod deplug eh tub
,ylsuoicarg dewob
...“ ,daeh sih koohs uzlaT
.esol ot I dah gnihton dna
,delur eh ytic eht dnuof
,ton srettam erofereht dna
,erutseg a htiw etyloca denrecnoc eht dehsuh
.robrah eht morf klaw s’ruoh na flah tuoba
,smra sih ni nekorb eb rehtar dluow I“
,noil eht dlot eh
.rotatcepS esirnuS eht
uzlaT dewollof evah dluow flow dlo eht
.ot niatta wef dna fo maerd nem lla ynitsed fo dnik eht ,enorht a dna yrolG
,yrrat uoy od yhW“
,htap siht no ,smaerd ehT“
,trap s’god eht roF
,ylteiuq derepsihw uzlaT ”spahrep dnA“
,gnillet-enutrof erem dna ytisoiruc otni dedaf
.nials eb dluow setarip eht gnoma yna fi deksa dah lla dna
”,yawa ma I nehw ,oS“
,thgit mih gnihctulc
.wonk uoy ,ereh decitnerppa ton saw I“
,tfig eht ton dah tub
,drawrof pets woN
.dehsdoolb elttil tub htiw
.yad eht gnirud ti ees ot dettimrep mirglip a saw ylerar rof
,aiglatson htiw yvaeh
”.ot deen ton od I“
,llih nretnal reh nopu
,htap eht pu edorts eh sa
,yrautcnas eht ot deyenruoj uoY
,elsi sih dna mih tfel tub eh fi
,niamer ot esoohc ohw yna fo ssel on kniht llahs I dna
,draeh eb ot gnitiaw uzlaT was eh nehw
deksa uoy ,nihtiw emac uoy
suoicarg erom lla ylneddus erew elsI tircO fo semoh eht dna—
,enim naht erom hcum eb ot mih snaem etaF
!og dluohs eh esuaceB“ ”?eow siht yhW
,ti fo esool ekahs ot dah I
eitros tsal eht ylekil saw dias etarip eht tahw no gnitraped
,raeb ot ksa ton did uoy
,uoy hctef ot emoc lliw etyloca nA
”.evael yam I erofeb
,raen nward evah dluow namutsiH
ksat tsal eht si
,flow dlo eht dnA .enog dah sexanauO hcihw drawot noziroh eht no dexif woh dna ,erew seye s’god eht ediw woh ,puc eht deppirg uzlaT thgit woh gniciton tsrif no ,neht ,tnelis nellaf evah dluow namautsiH ”.ynitsed s’oreh a sa
,yllufssilb ,yllufecaep
,srolias sih fo lufpihs a dna
,dne eht ta yenoh fo pord a
.saes nretsew eht revo tes nus eht hctaw ot sffulb hgih eht ot tub ,nrevat eht ro
,htuos eht ni sgniK-doG eht morf esnecni dna dlog gniraeb ,dias eh
,em llet uoy lliW
,etubirt htiw nedal-yvaeh
.enola eromreverof eb dna ,nworc rof
htiw eb oT .reven“ ,sessik neewteb ,noil eht debbos ”,yaN“ .regnuh etarepsed a htiw mih gnissik
”?em htiw sdrow evah dluow uoy“
thguoht ,htuom sih denepo eH
.elsI tircO no gnillewd sih eb ot ,robrah eht morf klaw s’ruoh flah a
.nruter a gninetaerht syawla
,enam sih hguorht wap a nar sexanauO
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
,deticer evah dluow namutsiH
”?uoy gnoma ereh si uzlaT fi wonk I yam :yas lliw I oS
,morf emac eh saw ti reverehw snruter eh fi ,sevael eh fI
,ecaf sih deldarc taht ylleb eht delzzun noil eht ”,llacer od I“
pu ti koot etyloca rehtonA
.erac ecracs lliw eh neht yB
?ereh ,sexanauO gniK
,htaerb doog a nekat evah dluow namutsiH
enon saw ereht tuB
ecalap a dliub ot desoprup ohw—
,gnitiaw uzlaT ees ot saw ti—
,raeh ot detnaw uoy tahw ton dlot eb thgim uoy taht—emaf reh
,delworg evah dluow
,frus eht koot taob eht ecnO .draoba tnew eh dna ,detnilg seye sih dna ,dehgual sexanauO ”!ruf ruoy tsniaga gnikirts tsom kool dluow stsyhtema ,llitS“
,msioreh dna yrolg s’devoleb sih fo smaerd eht
,yats ot ediced lliw eH“
em nopu nwod raeb dluow
sreizarb eht fo eno gnithgil saw elcaro ehT   ”.yas tonnac...“
.meht htiw denrut evah sdniw eht decnuonna sexanauO dna
,dne s’yenruoj ta elttab dna—meht nopu saw
,dias evah dluow namutsiH
,egaruoc sih ni dehtaerb sexanauO ”,llew yreV“
,pihsgnik ni flesmih sesol eh“
ytic a fo demaerd eh ,tsal eht nO
.dal ,uoy rof elcaro eht yalp lliw I“ ,ylluftsiw
,ogniD mailliW yb daeR   .sseug thgim
,serif ratla eht tiler eh dna
,dehgual uzlaT ”,esoppus I“
,sevol eh eno eht rof
,liat eht deciton yna fI ”.mih ot
nem ot etaf htekaeps taht mih teL .sraew etaf
ynitsed a ton taht si ,yhw
.rehtona eno gnikees
llits erew I tahT
,ereh llewd ot efas eb dluow ti
.ytnelp dna ecaep erotser dna
,thgiserof ym fo yretsam eht ot emac I nehw ,yhw si taht dnA
,kcen eht fo edis eht no
ecifircas ekam dluohs ehs sdog hcihw ot
nedrag yrautcnas eht ni puc tsafkaerb sih dehctulc god eht ”,eurT“
”.ytilatipsoh dereffo detcejer I taht“
,erusaert eht ot gniees naht rehtar
.strop rieht ni stnahcrem eht lla tuhs ot emac smrots retniw erofeb
,ereh tsap spihs rieht dnes ot naht retteb wonk smodgnik yttep eht yllautnevE .elbakramernu era esoht dna
”?lesnuoc uoy evig ot ton fi
,ssalg sa raelc dna
.taht ot yas ot gnihton dah evah dluow namutsiH
”?ereht ,sexanauO gniK
gnuoY saW dlroW eht nehW ygolohtna gninniw drawa eht morf
,won ereht ton saw eh yhw fo
ytrap s’elcnu sih fo ynam woh yas dluoc ohw rof