.selddup egral gninnaps sknalp nedoow dna ,enotselbboc
,derised netfo dah nareiK .orazzaL noD
,edistuo morf emac latem fo gnirettalc ehT
?esirprus eht siht sI“
eciov detatiga dna prahs eht detpure mih dniheB
.moor eht ot
.skcol gnurps tseivaeh eht tsniaga neve
,rood eht ta ylideerg dellup eH
,yltnecer tsuj gnissap ni neeb dah hctaw thgin eht duol woh gniredisnoC .detatiseh eH
.knukS dna htaerb-reeB ot degnoleb
deb fo tuo gnilwarc ,derumrum tiK
,rae decils sih yb ylno hguoht
,revewoh ,nareiK oT
,nwod dekcilf rae siH
.sehcni yb xof eht gnissim
.emanresu  emas eht htiw rettiwt a sah osla eH
”ekaC evaH mehT teL“
.napizram dna maerc eht otni dekrow ylluferac seirrehc dna seirrebwarts dah ekac eht fo esab ehT
.taht wonk uoy ,sesicrexe yliaD
.steerts eht gniklaw enoyna ot evisserpmi saw thgieh reehs riehT
.emoh tsomla saw eh
,hguone erus dna ,renroc a dednuor sdraug owt ehT
,edisni dezeeuqs eh ,gnihgiS
,rae doog sih tsap dezzihw tellub A   !KCARC
.tey nees dah xof eht ekac suoicerp tsom eht saw tI
.sselhceeps yllauqe htoB
.revewoh ,ekac lufituaeb eht ot gnulc llits eH
.emit eht dah yllanif eh
ylluferac deppets eH
.nissassa layor a fo krow drah eht rof noitaicerppa yna dah
,ytrid dna hguot saw krow ehT
.yzzid tlef eh ylnedduS
.tsol d’eh eno eht ot lacitnedi tsomla
.sepahs lufruoloc ,dnuor wef a detneserp lesaew ehT ”?huh ,sraey owT
,kaerb ro dneb reven dluow dna
.teksum sih morf desaeler dah eh ekoms fo ffup eht hguorht knukS detuohs
.sdrow rof tsol yletelpmoc
.mih trofmoc ot gniyrt
,tnecs sih fo secart tniaf deirrac llits hcihw ,rood der eht hguorht gnissaP
,leets degrof eltsac
”,ecalp tsrif eht ni em morf nelots ton d’uoy fi deifsitas erom neeb evah d’I“
htlaew dna sutats sih htiw deruomane os emoceb dah eH
fehc yrtsap suomaf eht ot degnoleb rood ehT
,dedihc knukS”,t’ndid uoy ,oN“ ”.mih toG“
,krow ot tog nareiK
,tiK ,dneirfyob sih neve toN
desilaer eh nehw
.emahs desiugsid ylroop htiw delbmum nareiK
,thgir sgniht ekam ot emoc ev’I“
.meht fo wenk eh tahw morf
?wonk uoy ,fehc yrtsap eht
,pohs ruoy naelc ll’I
,ylthgit rettalp ekac eht deppirg eH
.ydaerla em desuac evah uoy ecneinevnocni eht rof yenom ruoy ekat ll’I
,nevaeh fo etsat lliw ti hguoht dna ,edam ylitsah si eno sihT
,thgil kaew eht ni tnilg dluow sgnaf nedlog owt
.xof derae-on a mih ekam ot gninetaerht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”…I os ,tuo erew uoy tub ,gninrom siht devirra tI
”.detnaw I tahw ton s’tahT ?lesaew das A
.nevo eht otni dluom ekac eht dehsup eh sa swap sih morf ruolf dehsurb orazzaL noD ”.taht ekil erew nik ruoy fo erom hsiw I
.mih dnuora sesuoh eht ni ekawa llits elpoep eb thgim ereht
welb dniw fo tsug A
.esle gnihton fi ,erehpsomta dna gnittes fo eulav eht dootsrednu xof ehT
.stneve s’thgin tsal retfa pu-em-kcip a dnim t’ndluow eh dna
”,ris ,pu evas ot evah ll’I“
,orazzaL noD morf ekac a rof redro na ecalp ot ecarG siH deksa I ,oga syad emoS“
,won enog raf erew sdraug ehT
.dewollaws nareiK ”?em rof-
,gniliar ynoclab roolf-tsrif a fo edis gnorw eht no dnal ot deganam eH
,flesmih meht ezitpab ot dah nareiK os
.tnaw uoy revetahw od ll’I
.ekac eht htiw neve ylbissoP
.tnavres tnenimorp a sa boj sih fo dne eht neeb ev’dluow ti ,gnilaets nees saw tiK fI
.sretrauq reroop eht ssorca lla
,tsae eht morf detcepxenu
,ekuD eht fo telav lanosrep eht
,wap eno ni ekac sih gnicnalaB .egdirb eht otno
,ylthgils gniggaw saw liat trohs siH
”…rof ezigolopa ot dna
”,ot evah t’ndid uoY“
.dluow seidal dna sdrol eht woh ekil
.snap dna stop ,sehsid s’orazzaL noD fo lla fo erac koot dna ,ylluferac ecafrus yreve denaelc eH
,edaçaf raggeb sih gniyarteb
,dlrow eht tsniaga snis ruoy rof tneper ot kcab emac uoy taht elbadnemmoc si ti tuB“
,ylreporp meht yojne dna
.tsehc s’nareiK otni derumrum tiK
,dias orazzaL noD
.ekac emos rof eid ot yllis yllufwa eb dluow tI
.mih rof erots ni esirprus a etiuq eb ot gniog saw ereht dna
.ksir tuohtiw mih ta erif dluoc yeht
?orazzaL noD fo tnemhsilbatse eritne eht naelc dluow uoY“
,denetaerht ,detanosrepmi
.did eh tahw ta doog oot neeb dah eH
.eno siht sa hcus
,dethgink eb reve ot ylekilnu saw eh tub ,knar yb eriuqs a saw nareiK
,xof ,uoy rebmemer ll’I
”!uoy llik ton t’now ew dna ,won nwod emoc ,yeH
,esion a draeh eh ,ylnedduS
,sfoor eht fo pot no ydaerla saw nareiK
,retal syad wef A
,gninnur deppots dah htaerB-reeB dna knukS taht woN
.troffe sih erimda ot tnemom a rof kcab doots eH
ylthgils deliatruc ecnayonna sih
,ekac eht flah derevoc
,oN .feiht a toN
,spih sih htiw nepo rood eht devohs
,pil sih no dewehc dna
sgel riahc eht tsniaga yldipar liat sih deggaw eh
?raeppasid ot erew ti fi eciton dluow ohW
ylthgit epor eht deppirg eh
.smra sih ni lesaew etihw a htiw
.egde eht sdrawot gnireggats dna gnireteet
rood der s’fehc yrtsap eht fo ssalg eht tsniaga pu tuons kcalb sih dehsup d’eh emit a ynaM
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ffutsyttopS yb
.dlog rof tsuj ekab t’nod I“
.denilpicsid dna tneiciffe
,levarg revo deddap eh
seidal dna sdrol hsifles esoht lla fo thguoht ehT
.cirtnecce etiuq meht edam evah tsum
.nworc eht fo ecivres ni dellik dna ,delb
.emac eh yaw eht gninruter erofeb ssap ot meht rof gnitiaw
.ylneddus egdirb eht dekcor dna
.enecs emirc sih ot kcab yaw sih edam eH
,tsud dna hguod htiw dettam saw ruf s’nareiK ,noonretfa emoC
.esrever ni sdnuor rieht gninruter erew sdraug eht dna
.thgin yreve sdnuor emas eht edam yeht
,nar eh sa ylkciuq sesuoh eht fo sllaw eht dennacs eH
.dlrow siht ni nosrep eno rof spil sih ecarg ylno dluow ti tub
htlif dna etsaw fo tnecs dnuorgkcab tnatsnoc ehT
,orazzaL noD yllaicepse
.gnisac ssalg eht detfil eh ,elbon neve
,yllaeR“ ”…xof ,no dloH“
.deloord tub lla eh
.devaheb llew dna ,nekops-llew
”.uoy geb I ,niaga ekac taht ekam esaelP
,ssenevigrof ruoy ksa ,segamad eht rof yap ot emac I“
,emorhconom dna llud dekool yehT
.retnuoc s’tar eht no yenom eht tup dna
,worran os saw teerts eht dna
.erusaert sih morf noitnetta sih gnivomer tnemom a rof reven
”,teews gnihtemos yrt ot detnaw uoy dias syawla uoY“
.seye ypeels sih ni tnilg revelc a dah eh dna
,kcoltnilf deretsloh a dna
.sdoog sih detsat reven tub
,elbat eht yb riahc a no detaeS
.tbuod on saw ereht tub ,seye sih debbur dna deknilb eH
.taom wollahs a ssorca
,dneirfyob nwo sih morf ekac lufrednow taht nelots d’eH
.gnilffins ,dias tiK ”…nareiK ,hO“
.erusaert a deciton eh nehT
.ylduol denialpmoc segnih eht
,ksum knuks fo tnecs ehT
.deneppah ti ,nehT
,worran sa tsuj ,eno rehtona otni dna
.enola klaw ot emit suoiracerp a saw ti nwot fo trap siht ni dna
,elttil a dellips tsuj d’eh fI
.ylevitcnitsni roolf eht ot wol desserp dna
.taom eht otni dna
.rettalp denmad elohw eht saw ti
”.niaga ekac taht ekam ot uoy geb ot dna
.edisni stnecs tniaf eht gnihctac fo sepoh ni
.erofeb semit ynam doots d’eh hcihw fo edistuo
.wodniw eht fo edis rehto eht morf meht nees dah nareiK nehw sa gnicitne sa ton wohemos
mih ta kcab dekool dneirfyob sih dna
?ksa ot hcum denmad os taht saw
,sserttam eht no nwod kcab tas nareiK  ”.esirprus A
.kaerc elbakatsimnu na pu kcip ot dekrep rae doog siH
,snap dna stop ruoy hsaw ll’I
”?tahw sseug ,nareiK“
.swap sih htiw ecaf sih gnirevoc dna kcab pil sih gniward ,decniw nareiK
,xof eht wenk yehT .hctaw thgin ehT
.ecnalab sih fo deniamer taht elttil tahw mih gnitsoc
,tnew eh teerts eht ssorca kcaB
smelborp gnikam devlovni reerac elohw s’nareiK
,tar tnamrod a deniatnoc dah hcihw
.yaw eno ylno saw erehT
.flesmih trofmoc t’ndluoc eh tuB
,tnaem I tahw toN“
.ecnahc a doots reven tI
,enif morf edam skcipkcol ytilauq doog erew yehT
.renroc eht ni moorb dna tekcub a ot yllufgninaem dekool dna
,sruoloc eht erew secnereffid ylno ehT
ti ssorca maerc deppihw daerps eH
.yrasrevinna rieht no ton ,siht ekil toN
”…uoy taht yas ot naem uoY“
,lesrom elttil a saw detnaw eh llA
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.lortap llaw yna naht rehtar
,pu deps setalptsaerb gnirettalc fo sdnuos ehT
nirg sih dehsalf nareiK
.ruf etihw thgirb sih revo nwog gninrom a gnipard dna
llaw ytic eht fo yawklaw daorb eht deniag dna
,yawateg sih repmah ylereves thgim ekac eht gniyrraC
.gnir s’nareiK ta derutseg tar ehT
.deriuqer eh egaruoc eht dnuof eh
.ti nekat dna ,elbon a ot degnoleb ti thguoht evah tsum enoemoS
.tohs dnoces a rof hguone kciuq ton tub ,yllacitnarf gnidaoler saw knukS
,draytruoc eht hguorht dna sriats esuohetag eht nwod ,egdirb eht ssorca deddap eH
.epacse fo htap sih tuo dennalp dna
.denigami evah dluoc eh naht retaerg saw tlef eh riapsed eht dna ,deirc nareiK ”!ON“
.rood sih morf emac kaerc a nehw detpurretni saw noitartnecnoc siH
.sliar nori thguorw eht rof depsarg eno rehto eht sa
.detixe lesaew elttil eht sa dneirfyob sih ta ylgninoitseuq gnikool
”,uoy ot ton yllaicepse ,elas rof si ereh gnihtoN
.smihw modnar rieht terpretni ot denrael reven tub ,skeew rof meht deiduts dah eH
.evitom laitini sih fo sseldrager
si yrots s’yadot dna
.emas eht lla derrab saw eh suht dna
?roolf ytrid ylgnisirprus siht no seenk sih no teg eh dluohS ?geb ot evah eh dluoW .tar eht ot yltnatiseh dekool eH
.koot ti revetahw ,daetsni niaga retteb ti ekam dluow eH
gniht tnetop ylevitacove dna gnisimorp
,nareiK ekil ton saw eH
,ssorca yaw rehto on saw ereht tuB
,erus ,ecalp ytrid a saw ytic sihT
.eltsac eht rof era seirtsap esehT .yob ,tuo teG“
,rettalp sti no deniamer ti tub ,retsinab eht morf gnarps neht dna
,lesaew eht gnihctulc llits ,sserttam sih otno nwod degnulp eH
.won maerc fo swap sih kcil thgim eh
,ecnalab rof edis eht ot liat sih gnihsal
.sdraug gnillortap fo sehcrot eht morf rekcilf on was eH
.mih no gniees rebmemer reve dluoc nareiK skool tseddas eht fo eno htiw
.tliug fo gnits rettib eht htiw ssenteews taht tniat ot erad t’ndid eH .ydnac ton
.steehs sih htaenrednu pu delruc dna ,rebmahcdeb sih ot denruter eH
.ssendas htiw ti gnicalper
.ti no sgnivas ym lla tneps I
,llaw ytic eht ta elzzum sih detniop eH
.ecitcarp dna ecneirepxe fo sraey revo
,nevenu dna detnals saw ti hguohT
,gnikced nedoow yreppils eht no
,thgin lamron a no meht nurtuo evah ylisae dluoc eH
,gnuts steews eht fo ssol ehT
,pal sih no mitciv sih dleh eh woN
?ekac taht gniees retfa ,niaga doof raluger ot kcab og eh dluoc woH
,nwot fo trap siht ni stnecs rehto eht lla morf flesti dehsiugnitsid tI
yeht tuB .steerts eseht fo ria eht gnitaemrep sllems fo ssem eht ni
,ecnartne stnavres eht edisni mih tel retrop ehT
.rehto hcae ta gnirats ereht dnats ylno dluoc yeht tnemom a roF
noitcefrep ot denoh ,lliks erar A
.emit siht daeh sih evoba sdraobroolf eht morf
,pu sllems eseht kcip dluoc ohw enoyna ot dna ,sllems tnereffid fo ssem a emac meht morf tuB
”,sdraug eht llac t’nod I dalg eb dluohs uoY“
.demahsa derumrum nareiK
.retaw dna paos ni dehcnerd dna
.deined dna ta detuohs eb ot renommoc rehtona tub saw nareiK
trofmoc dna htmraw rof
.orazzaL noD fo tfarc eht etsat ot epoh reve dluoc renommoc oN
,yojne dluoc selbon eht staert rehto fo aes eht gnomA
.dah orazzaL noD hcihw
.gniggaw morf liat sih pots t’ndluoc eH
.moor eht ni sekac owt erew erehT
edirp detalfni taht tuohtiw
F“ ”.xof ,yrros m’I .enog s’tI
,ekac tneconni dna ecin a fo dlrow eht devirped eh dah ylno toN
…nees saw nareiK fI
sroolf eht debburcs eh erehw sretrauq etavirp s’tar eht ot no devom eH
.noitnetta sih tog thgil fo rekcilf A
.gnissim saw eh gnihtemos saw erehT
noos kcab eb dluow lesaew ehT
.dehgual htaerB-reeB
.krad retfa tuo emoc yllausu dluow serugif yruovasnu dna dekaolC
.xof ,yrasrevinna yppaH“
,sdraug egnarts eseht fo serusaelp elbamohtafnu dna esrevrep eht rof yltsom detsixe ti erus saw nareiK
wap s’nareiK no gnir tengis ybur nedlog eht morf dellevart seye s’orazzaL noD
,emac kaerc rehtonA .wolg gnirekcilf
.no sehtolc sih htiw swap sih ni dleh reve d’eh
.swap sih ni gnihtemos gnidloh saw eh
slirtson s’nareiK otni detfird
.niaga sgel lufrewop sih dekcik eh
.ees ot srehto detnaw eh revetahw saw ecnaraeppa siH
…ees I“ .enot yrgna sih gniniartser
.yrekab eht edisni morf emac draeh dah eh esion ehT
.dias nareiK ”,erofeb sroolf debburcs evah I“
.esnes fo tnuoma tsael eht edam tahw enod niaga dah srepeeketag ehT
.mih htaenrednu delbbow egdirb eht sa
.lla ti tuoba gnileef dab a dah eh tub
.gnihton tog eh dna ,erahs rieht tog selbon eht llA .mih gnikcom
”?nedrub taht fo orazzaL noD eraps ylgnilliw dluow uoY
”?emit ruoy fo tnemom a ,ris snodrap yM“
dekram erom gniworg
,gab sih otni lla meht dellevohs eh tub
.yrrufoS no serutnevda s’nareiK tuoba seirots erom tuo tup ot sepoh eH
”,em ot pu ti ekam t’nac uoy nehT“
.ecnailpmoc sih fo eetnaraug on saw ti
,spahrep rellik deniart a rof noitcaer elbatiusnu nA
,deifitsuj saw tfeht siht taht flesmih decnivnoc gnivaH .ekac emos rof
.ecnalg dnoces a droffa t’ndluow eno mohw retcarahc dnuorgkcab emos otni mih denrut swodahs ehT .yltcefrep
senots gnivap eht eb llew sa thgim selit ehT
,citegolopanu dna gnorts
.thginot peels ot yrt thgim reveohw enola tel
.mih erofeb tra fo eceip etalucammi eht yawa seye sih ekat ton dluoc nareiK
.seye sih revo nwod dellup dooh sih htiw rood eht tsniaga gninael
,ssenkrad ni deduorhs neeb dah hcihw ,sriats ehT .t’ndid won dna
.nees gnieb diova ot evah d’eH ,llew
,toof a naht erom ti nepo dluoc eh erofeb tub
.skaep rieht ta hcuot ot demees yeht taht
,ti detsat evah dluoc eh taht esolc oS
tekcop a ni dnuora gud eH
,dneirfyob sih htiw thgin eht erahs dna eniw fo elttob a nepo d’eH
.detsuahxe dna dednepxe yrtsitra eht dna
.taert siht evresed t’ndid yeht ,yleruS
.hteet dettirg hguorht denaorg eH ”,on-on-on-oN
.skcart sih ni deppots tar eht tub
.ylkciuq ,tca ot dah eH
,pohs elttil eht ni edih dluoc eh yaw on saw ereht desilaer xof ehT
.thgilhcrot eht ni ekac eht gniyduts
eceipretsam etihw dna kcalb sihT
,trats daeh sih htiw emit emos flesmih thguob dah eH
.traehteews ,rettam eht s’tahW“
,woleb teerts eht otno nwod deniar dna
,moor eht deretne tiK
.enot wol a ni gnikaeps
,mih tops ot eb tsum ti ysae woH
emit sih ekat dluow eH
.woleb seciov tniaf pu dekcip eh
.ees ot evah uoy gnihtemos s’erehT“
.depoord sreksihw sih dna
.hguone kciuq ton saw ecap sih desilaer noos eH
.teef sih ot gnikool ,detatiseh tiK
,htap sih no yawrood tseraen eht rof demia eH .hsaw t’ndid ohw
,talf erew srae dnuor siH
.tuo neeb d’eh elihw desiar neeb dah egdirbward ehT
,ytilaer eht denetfos ecneserp siH
.hgih dleh nip gnillor
latem no latem fo sdnuos gnirettalc ehT
.ekoj elbeef sih ta elims t’ndid tiK tub
,ria eht otni welf ekac ehT
,tsirw sih dnuora wap mraw a tlef eh ,deb fo tuo teg ot devom eh nehW
,swap s’lesaew eht ni ekac rehtona
.gnidliub tnemeticxe sih leef dluoc eH
ffatsekip a htiw raeb nworb egral a
,nareiK ot ytilamrof a ylerab kcol sti
.yawa yenom sih gnivaw
.mih evoba sesuoh dedworc eht fo llems eht htiw ylecin ni dednelb tnecs siH
...snehctik eht ni dekool I nehw tuB
,detartlifni ,kcuns dah eh
,yrekab eht ni edih ot dennalp dah
,gnah ot demees ti erehw
.teerts eht fo dne eht sdrawot gniklaw deunitnoc nareiK
,edis eht ot deyalps rae doog sih dah eH .dedaelp nareiK
.mih was ron dellems rehtien
N“  ”?xof ,ekac a ekam ot woh wonk uoy oD“
,renwo sti morf ton yllaicepse
dna depahs llew saw tI
,daed eht ekaw ot hguone duol gnisrevnoc erew yehT
,hguone neeb dah fi nevE
kcab sih no teksum gnol a htiw knuks etihw dna kcalb a dna
.mrof etalucammi sti morf nellaf dah yrreb ro bmurc elgnis a ton ,enitsirp
.tleb sih no gab savnac eht yb deipucco neeb dah sehcni yrev esoht ,yletanutrofnU
.kciuq taht nur t’ndluoc eh
.xof ,neht no kaepS
.eromyna yrgna t’nsaw eh tub ,delbmum tar ehT
,eltsur ot demees reven ebor sih yhw
,ekac fo eceip a regnol on saw yralgrub sihT
,gaw t’ndid liat siH
no ylsselpleh kool ylno dluoc nareiK
,elbat eht no ekac etihw dna kcalb eht ot xof eht morf dellevart seye s’tiK
,ssenkrad eht tsniaga etihw gniremmihs ,maerc deppihw
,tiK tuoba thguoht eh nehw tub
.llaw retuo s’eltsac eht no esuohetag rehtona etisoppo doots hcihw
.flesmih rof yrros gnileef dna gnirettum
,aitamlaD ni eno oN
”?uoy rehtob enoemos diD
.tuhs rood eht dloh neve ot htgnerts tneiciffus ylerab fo ecnavirtnoc dellerrab-elgnis ylsaem a
.reppus tnaw t’ndid eH
yenom s’nareiK tpecca ylippah dluow htimskcalb eltsac eht ,yllufknahT
,mih gnitpmet ,mih gnicitnE
.sesuohetag owt eht fo spot eht neewteb egdirb epor worran ,elgnis a dednepsus dah yeht taht os hcum oS
”.snehctik eht morf yawa gnihtemos kaens ot decnahc I os ,dab tlef I“
,seitilamrof egnahcxe ot hguone esolc teg ot deganam reven yehT
.sgnik ekil gnigrog
,slliswodniw ybraen eht fo eno otno depmuj eH
.esolc os reve saw eh dna
,egnops eht dna moorb eht ekat lliw uoY
.gniog teg ot evah I“ .deksa nareiK ”?woN ?tiK
,lufituaeb tsom eht neeb dah tI
”…m’I yhw s’taht ,ris on-
”?deifsitas er’uoy naem taht seoD“
,hcamots eht ot kcik a devresed eh ekil tlef nareiK
stnemhsilbatse elbatcepser dna enif ni
,kaolc sih kcab werd eH
.tbuod on ,egrahc ni snaitamlaD eht dna truoc layor eht ot egamoh nA
.swodniw eht denaelc dna
.niaga xof derae-eno taht s’tI“
,llufwap a koot nareiK  .elbaekatsimnu
,htob meht rof setalp tuo tup eH
.stnavres nrob-wol fo elpuoc a rof suoicerp oot raf erew yehT
etapissid tliug sih tlef eh ,egnops eht fo burcs dna
.sthguoht sih dellif tnemtnioppasid detulidnu dna
elbat a no gnirevoc ssalg a rednu doots ekac lufituaeb A
.elzzum sih no elims a tup ot denetaerht dna
.sdraug ybraen eht rof dellac ti sa tar elbarenev eht fo
,ytic eht fo egde eht dehcaer eh nehW .nar dna
,tnorf pohs gnisoppo na fo lliswodniw eht fo pot eht no esahcrup dnuof eh sa noos sA
”ekaC evaH mehT teL“:yojne esaelP
,flesmih ot evah dluoc eh taht esidarap fo eceip etunim tsom eht tsuJ ,etib ynit a
,tnecs sih htiw ton
.tsol neeb dah selbram elttil gnillems-teews eht fo eno elgnis yrevE
.skcalb dna syerg ni tuo dehsaw erew hcihw
.dnoces gnissap yreve htiw reraen werd sruomra s’draug eht fo gnilttar ehT
enoemos rof lufecarg os erew stnemevom sih yhw
gninrom txen eht pu ekow eH
.ekac a deirrac eh dna
.xof eht ta tsif derevoc-ruolf a gnikahs
.feiht eht neeb d’eh taht timda eh dluoc rehtieN
”?thgir ,stnuoc taht thguoht eht s’tI“
teknalb a ekil gnuh
,slirtson sih tih ria mraw ,teews eht nehw dna
teksum a deirrac knukS
,ti morf yawa gnikcik erofeb
.elbat wol sih no ekac eht detisoped eH
!oN“ .sreusrup owt sih fo stemleh eht tsniaga ylsselmrah gnirettalc
dna meht detapicitna d’eH
.emoh yaw sih ekam dluoc eh
,pag tsal eht ssorca decnuob eh
nehctik eht dellif amora ylnevaeh s’tI
.gninrut peek dluow dlrow eht dna
.no mih gnidaog yltnatsnoc saw ekac eht fo llems ehT
,niht a htiw ,dedaelp nareiK
.thginot sdon railimaf egnahcxe t’ndid eh tub
.dnuof eb dluoc ytirup erehw ecalp eno saw ereht tub
…ll’I“ .eciov gnikcarc
.rehgih dna rehgih ,gnidliub ot gnidliub
.sruomur eht draeh dah ohw enoyna sa llew sa
,raelc saw htap ehT
.denodnaba ylgnimees dna krad ,sffilc ekil doots mih dnuora sesuoh ehT
,won delims eh fI
”.lufesu flesruoy ekam dna
,edis rehto eht no yal tahw fo thguoht eht ta detavilas eH
.segaw sih fo htrow s’raey a flah tsomla
.nameltneg s’nameltneg eurt A
,esaelp ,taht od t’noD“
,dias orazzaL noD
.xof ,flesruoy rof tub hsaw ot erom gnihton s’ereht esoppus I“
”,gnihtemos hctef ll’I .laiceps si yadot
,ynoclab ot ynoclab morf depmuj eH
.ekac nelots eht ecalper ot detnesnoc ecarg siH“
”…ot tnaw llits uoy fi ruoh na ni kcab eb ll’I
wohemos d’eh hcihw ,ezirp laer eht no sucof sih tpek eh tub
,yawa detfird dah stnecs rieht dna ,dessap dah yeht sa noos sA
.devresed eh tlef nareiK tahw tsuj saw ti tub
tops emas eht ta gnikool fo syad ylenol esoht llA
.etatiseh ot demees orazzaL noD
…b ym morf tfig a saw tI
.txen eht ot teerts rehtona ssorca neht dna
xof elttil eht dnuora flesmih depparw dna
.pohs yrev siht ni sa llew sa
...eht tsniaga saw eh sa detteuohlis ,mih no daeb a ward dna
.seye ypeels htiw
.ecniw mih edam dna
.lesaew etihw a dna xof kcalb a rof tcefrep eb dluow
.elbaod tuoba tsuj saw ti
.mih dethgiled ssel-ekac dna detartsurf
,tnorf pohs a ot pu werd eH
.erehwyna gniog t’nsaw nareiK
.flesmih evas ot sepor eht rof depsarg eh ,ylevitcnitsnI
.etaf sti delaes hsalps llams A
.reppus sih rof nocab gnimmiks tuoba gnikniht neve tuohtiw nehctik eht hguorht tnew eH
.did eh tahw ta doog saw nareiK
.teerts eht fo edis etisoppo eht sdrawot
,noitom wols ni sa flesmih was eH
.nevo eht fo tuo emac ekac eht
.tnecs xof eht dna ,taoc kcalb
,yltnecer gnitirw detrats ohw tsitra lausiv a ,ffutsyttopS yb
,pils gnitoof sih tlef nareiK
.gnidahs tuoba nrael ot naht reisae eb dluow ti thguoht ylhsiloof eh esuaceb
.tiK sselpleh rooP
.rossecederp sti ekil dekool ti
.denrut tiK sa tem seye riehT
.morf emoc dah eh eno eht sa worran sa ,teerts edis worran rehtona otni depacse eH
.yad txen eht ytrap emos rof tnaem ylbaborp saw tI
,ylralucitrap sekac dna steews ni desilaiceps eH
.swap sih htiw deppirg ro ,teef sih detnalp ro
dnuof seye s’nareiK dna
.mih erofeb gnileenk saw ohw ,nareiK ot kcab dekool eH
,sroiretxe rieht depard seinoclab llamS
tnedifnoc leef ot mih rof elbissopmi saw tI
,melborp yna tuohtiw ssorca syaw flah nettog d’eh nehW
”!haH“  .epoh llits saw erehT
steerts tilhcrot eht hguorht devom
.deretne tsuj dah eh moor krad eht ni dnuora dekool nareiK
?yltcaxe tahW …sdeelb eh kniht uoy sselnU“
.deniart saw eh woh tsuj saw tahT
,nwod dna pu xof eht dekool eH
elpoep fo lluf saw modgnik siht taht lufknaht saw xof eht ,ecno roF
erew ragus dna stiurf fo stnecs teews rieht ,os nevE
.foor eht niag ot emit tsal eht rof teerts eht ssorca tluav ot deraperp dna
”ekaC evaH mehT teL“ saw sihT
.semag eseht no thgin siht etsaw ot tnaw t’ndid eh
moorb eht fo hsurb yreve htiW
,nissassa layor a rof elbatius ton dna
”?htrae no yhW ?steewS
,thgil elttil dedivorp sehcrot dna snretnal derettacs wef ehT
.deldniker epoh sih dna
,derumrum nareiK
.tleb sih morf gnuls dah eh gab savnac a otni ydnac eht gnippils ,rehtona neht
,pohs rehtona morf gnilaets xof rehtona tsuj saw eh ,llew ,hO
deb a fo kaerc ehT
”!feiht ,ereh nwod emoC“
.enituor esicrexe yliad a sa meht ssorca nur dah eh netfo woh gniredisnoc
.deredisnoc sgniht lla ,thgis lausunu na toN
.did eh sa kcul sih no nwod sa dekool ohw
saw eh gnikniht ni deifitsuj eb dluow enoynA
.nareiK ,elbirret s’ti ,hO“
,ni swalc sih gud eh woh fo sseldrager
.em rof tnaem saw ekac ehT …hO“
.noitagergnoc laicos fo sertnec suotoir sa deraeppa sesuoh eht
.steews eseht dedroffa neeb dah
.mih tih tnecs xof s’nareiK nehw
kcab yaw sih dnuof nareiK nehw tuo saw lesaew ehT  .deil nareiK ”,ekac siht ees lliw luos elgnis a ton ,ris esimorp I“ ”?dnatsrednU .ekac orazzaL noD a ton si ti
.gnizalg eht gnitoned tniap etihw htiw ,tonk a ni deit
.stnemelpmi latem niht fo ecarb a no llef thgil nretnal tniaf eht dna
.gnorw eb dluow yeht tuB .ydobon
.pohs sih edisni meht gnittel neve ton
,otno debmilc eh sa ylsuoiracerp delbbow ekac ehT
.emaceb eh detatiga erom eht
.yadot llew enod ev’uoY
emoclewnu ylralucitrap erew sexoF
,htrib rewol fo enoyna ot sdoog sih gnilles deppots eh taht
.retnuoc eht no steews drah fo sraj eht ta dekool eh nehw seye sih fo snoitatimil eht ta detnioppasid ylthgils tlef eH
.eciton trohs hcus no edam eb dluoc taht ekac ylno eht si sihT“
.erac decitcarp htiw draobroolf elgnis yreve gnibburcs
,ees dluoc eh taht tuo yaw a saw erehT
mih detius steerts eseht ni ssenkrad evisserppo eht
.ekac eht flah revoc ot seirrebkcalb derettacs eh hcihw otno ,savnac etihw a etaerc ot
mih fo tnorf ni noitcnuj eht gniraen erew hcihw stnecs owt ehT
.retnuas ysion a ta teerts eht nwod emac
.elbatnuomrusni saw ecirp sih dna
.niaga eugnot sih no tnemeticxe etsat ot detrats eh
,elzzum s’nareiK ot regnif a tuo dleh dna dias orazzaL noD
,mottob eht ni eloh egral a morf tuo dekael luah siH
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.stneve s’thgin tsal eht deviler nareiK sa
.lotsip sih htiw mia nekat dah mih ediseb raeb ehT
,reerac sih fo esruoc eht revO
,daor hgih dellevart-llew a fo
,taht nwonk dah eh tuB
.ti ecnahc ot erad t’ndid eH
,teerts worran eht gnola gniklaW
.gnivas neeb d’eh elttob eht morf teralc fo spuc owt deruop dna ,eldnac a til
,teerts eht ot esolc os deldduh erew yehT
”.raed ,yrasrevinna yppaH“
eud ni yletinifed saw eH
”.esirprus a eb ot tnaem saw tI“
.eraps ot teef lareves htiw
niaga tey teerts eht ssorca welf xof eht nehw neve
,xof elttil eht no decnavda dna hcneb eht dednuor eH
.meht detekcop eh os ,steews eht tae ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc eH
.revo saw tsrow eht
.ezeerb a no yltneg gnitfird fi sa
”.ekac siht ekat uoy erofeb ,xof ,gniht erom eno tsuJ“
”.yademos ekac orazzaL noD a yub ot uoy wolla thgim I
.pohs eht fo kcab eht ta
,ynoclab lanif eht ot tpael nareiK
.detsixe reven dah ekac eht fi sa saw tI
yawa detemmulp ti sa
.norpa etihw a ni desserd tar a yb tem saw eh
.mih ot kcab sih denrut dna dias tar ehT
.mih ot ekac taht nruter dluow stsetorp oN
.od ot tnow saw eh sa
detuohs tar ehT ”!uoy saw ti ,ekac tahT !uoY“
.ssol taerg on saw ti
”?deneppah s’tahW“ ”.lufwa tsuj s’tI
.detapicitna d’eh naht rewols enog dah bmilc siH
,redluohs sih revo deksa tiK
.sllems eht morf yawa gnidaeh saw eH
”.esaelP ,on-on-on …oN“
.gniggaw saw tI .tsrif liat
.tnirps ksirb a dehcaer ydaerla dah nareiK tub ,mih sdrawot emac dna
,yltnassecni spil sih dekcil dna
.tar hcir yrev a mih edam dah hcihw ,aitamlaD fo truoc eht ni emaf daerpsediw deyojne eH
,denwo eh htlaew eht lla tar eht thguorb d’eH
.orazzaL noD dna doG
,reerac sih fo tser eht rof naelc ylippah dluow eH
.emarf dna rood eht otno daerps tnecs sih taht erawa
.flah rehto eht derevoc napizram deruoloc fo kcalb laoc eht dna
.revewoh ,eveels sih pu eca na dah xof ehT  .hguone ton tub
.tfarc ot syad sekat ekac orazzaL noD eurt A
”.eciwt ekac a ekam ton lliw I
”.ris ,t’nod esaelP“
,wenk ohw esoht ot nissassa layor a sa mih deifitnedi hcihw
kaolc kciht a ni xof kcalb ,llams A   ffutsyttopS yb
,ruf sih morf hguod fo spmulc gnikcip saw nareiK sA
.elzzum sih ni sgnaf nedlog owt eht ot
.flesmih niatnoc yldrah dluoc nareiK
”!eturb bmud uoy ,toohs ,ylkciuQ“  ”?t’now eW“
”.uoyknahT .raey txen ebyaM“
,lotsip a deirrac htaerb-reeB tub
.thgin eht otni gnol mih edisni denrub terger ehT
,niar dna dniw eht tuo peek ot edam ylerem saw rood s’rekab ehT
…sgnillac rehgih evah I
.yrc ot tuoba saw eh ekil dekool eH
.etisoppo ynoclab yrots dnoces eht niag ot
,nekatrednu ruobal eht
tnecs railimaf s’nareiK fo ecart a etarapes dna tceted ot elba eb thgim yeht ,dehtab yeht daH
,smra sih ni lesaew eht ekat ot revo gnihsur ,demialcxe nareiK ”!tiK“
.rehtegotla noom eht morf thgil eht tuo gnikcolb semitemos
.denigami tsrif d’eh sa esolc sa neeb t’ndah eh taht dnuof eh nehT
.lesaew eht ot ylgniwonk dekniw dna
.draeh eb dluoc seciov fo sdnuos eht dna
,gnir tengis ybur dna dlog sih yalpsid t’ndluow eH
.esolc os neeb dah eH
,thgin eht gnirud ni emoc evah tsum tiK
.lesaew eht ot tnaem dah siht hcum woh dootsrednu nareiK
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.steerts krad eht otni nar dna
,lesaew tneconni dna ecin sih morf noitapicitna dna tnemeticxe eht nekat d’eh tub
,nageb krow rieht erofeb rehtegot tnemom a erahs ot meht rof lausunu toN
,delbmum nareiK ”,rentrap ym morf
.nwo sih htiw derewsna nareiK dna ,delims tiK
”.uoy ot pu ti ekam ot tnaw I
,demusnoc neeb ydaerla evah stneidergni ehT“
.efil sih htiw epacse ot mih wolla dluow hcihw lliks A
,wap elgnis a otno rettalp ekac eht gnippilf
.tcatni peek ot deganam
.lufruoloc gnihtemos tuo dellup dna
,llaw eht no ecnocs til ybraen a ot pu tnew eH
.reduol werg edistuo gnirettalc eht dna ,sriats eht ot sdraobroolf eht morf detfihs skaerc ehT
.llits thgieh erom gniniag
.yad eht ni sa krad eht ni llew sa tsuj ees dluoc eH
,htuom sih ni eno tsuj pop ot yldab os detnaw eH
.renroc eht ni tekcub dna moorb eht ta wap sih devaw tar ehT
,daerb gnikool suoiruc a fo gnitniap eht erob rood der ehT
sesuohetag owt eht detcennoc egdirbward A
,nur dluoc eh kciuq woh rettam oN
.remmilg t’ndid seye sih
,nihc sih dehctarcs tar ehT
,pot eht ot yawflah dnuorA
.ekac orazzaL noD rehtona dewo si dlrow eht ,tuB
.egdirb siht detah eH
,tsap delias tellub ehT !KCARC
”.kciuq ti ekaM
.esruoc fo ,xof eht tub enoyna ot ksir tuohtiW
.lesaew sih ot kcab elims a gnirb dluow ti fi
.dah eb ot bmurc a ton saw ereht tey dna
,txen eht ot teerts eht ssorca gnurps dna
,sseldnuos erew spetstoof sih yhw rednow ot pots reven thgim enO
.hgiht sih no tleb rehtael a ot depparts erew snoitulos sih ,thginoT .yawa og
”…ees uoY …lleW …naem I ,oN“
,egde sti ot foor eht gnola nar eH
,sdraug eht gnizinogatna ni dethgiled yllausu eh hguohT
,esuohetag a yb nekorb saw llaw gnidnuorrus s’ytic eht ,tniop tsomnrehtron sti tA
.thgin fo daed eht ni aitamlaD fo
,retal elttil a denruter yob ehT
.xof eht ot llef ksat siht
.maj teews htiw ekac gnilooc eht dellif orazzaL noD
,demoorg-llew ,lesaew enimre ytterp dna erup a saw eh
,tniaf a deriuqca ylneddus