,thgieh elbissopmi na ot esir—yas nac ohw
.yrautcnas s’elcaro eht dniheb neddih
,doohnam nrobaes fo soahc A
,dnabsuh reh ffo tup dah ehs dias romur won dna
,gnihsalps ,gnihgual
,sexanauO fo ,yaserad I
sretniw neves dna erocs elgnis fo dal erem a raeh ot“
,deworruf worb s’uzlaT
,erehw yllug eht ssorca
”?yad taht tekram eht ni dah eb ot esle gnihton ereht saw ,hO“ ”.ton did I“
,dlrow eht ees ,tuo oG
.rewsna on dah evah dluow namutsiH ,taht oT
raef htiw emocrevo oot erew yeht fi del erew smirglip erehw
erom gnihton sa wenk eh mohw
,ela fo lwob a tup
.lla retfa etirovaf sih si yllaer
.erohs eht ro ,nrevat eht ro
”?dnalsi riaf siht fo gnik uoy emuserp I
detsuahxe dereggats eh llit gnirevihs dna dekan—
,suoiruc si rotaro eht spahreP
,roirraw eht ssel mees
,daeherof sih no ssik s’elcaro eht htiw
.elcaro na gnieb fo nedrub eht
,setarip dna srolias
.taht eb dluow taht dnA
.yas ot elcarO na ekat yam“
,elppa nedlog ehT
,elsI tircO no llewd ot llits eno ylno eht saw
.thgin tsal dort evah dluow lareneg eht ,sserieh eht
.swodahs eht morf htrof spets etyloca deksam a sa
.etyloca na sa devres dah eH
.moor sih ni niamer ot mih detcepxe
.ecivres ym dna swov sih morf esaeler kees lliw eh taht
.ezorf dna denethgiarts uzlaT
”!pleh ton lliw em gnitcartsiD“
,wonk ot emoc dluow uzlaT
.em rof og ot desu uoy sa“
,ekam ot uzlaT ot
,semuf eht ni dehtaerb eH
,nam dlo na flesmih llac yaM
.kees ot emoc dah nam siht ohw ton saw uzlaT ?ti saw ,ereh detnaw saw tahw ton saw traeh
,desoppus eh ,erofereht dna
,yllaer ecnereffid eht si tahw os
kaeb a fo krawlub leurc
”.won em htiw yal uoy dnA“ ”.ecno ta og ot
.ssenkrad yvaeh esolc eht otni yawa sllor noitseuq rieht elihw ,suovren
tnaem evah dluoc ti tahw no rednop ot
redluohs erab sih fo selcsum eht revo ruf yksud fo llor eht
esiugsid gnihsillebme eht hguorht ees dluoc god eht
,yas dluoc elsi eht no esle enoyna ro ,eh sa raf sA
,rebmemer did eh hcihw taht dnA
,smra sih ni yal ohw god eht ot ,retfa
,tniap dna retsalp ylno ocserf a sllac ohw nam a yaw eht ni
”nwO siH fo etaF oN evaH neM ot etaF htekaepS taht miH teL“yojne esaelP
.noitcartsid a flesruoy dniF .tahw“
”.tnaw I thgua gnirb dluoc ohW“
.yarps tlas fo sllems enam nud eht
.dlrowrednu eht ton
”?taht sa ylkciuq os evol ni neht uoy erA“
dniheb tfel saw eh sa ,delffab
,nees dah eh esle tahw
,snemo dna sngis tsuj ton gninraeL
,detpurretni dah flow eht
sbreh dercas dna sdees ylio dna
.sdrayeniv on dah ti os
enola uoy dna flesym sti rof
,edis s’god eht pu nur ot devirtnoc wohemos
wets xoniuqe eht fo sgnikam eht kcab gnirb ot“
,emit a ta drow a
ria raelc naelc fo shtaerb peed ekat dna
,denialpxe eb dluoc
,meht fo owt eht fo tuB
uzlaT yad eht neeb dah taht dnA
,thgieh sih eciwt eb lliw ehs hguoht
nrets eht ot mih del dna
.sreizarb ralucaro nezod a fo semuf eht naht gnitacixotni erom saw elims taht
.efil reh ni ,ecno ta nees reve sah ehs htlaew tsom eht si tI
,ksa yehT .kaeps yeht oS
,demialced elcaro eht elihw
?tekram eht ta nediam yddur oN“
drawot ecap eht pu dekcip dna derettum uzlaT ”,yadot yttahc er’uoY“ ”.llew yap yeht
yrautcnas eht tfel noil ehT
,tsehc sih ssorca htolc nevow ylthgirb fo hsas a
,etyloca eht uzlaT ta kcab kool su tel oS
,sdog eht morf etaname sgniht fo serutan eurt eht mialc srehposolihp eht sa
,sterces sih retfa yrp ot derac enoyna fi
,ezeerf god eht tlef noil eht fi dna
ruf nworb-tlis siH
”?wonk uoy did woH“
”.lla retfa elcarO ruoy kees dna og tsal ta tsum I“
,mirglip on saw I wenk uoy“
.ecaf eurt sih erew ti fi sa
etyloca na neht dnA
,dias evah dluow namutsiH ”,em ssim uoY“
ho dna ,enam nwolbdniw sih hguorht swalc nar sexanauO ”.won litnu gniht a hcus saw ereht ton draeh I ,htiaf doog nI“ .deffuh uzlaT ”,tsrif eht era uoy
teL“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT
,ti gnignahc neht dna
,derebmemer eh esuaceb
.gnivom tuohtiw ,uzlaT dessih ”!wonk I“ ”.ecaep
,stuop sserieh eht dna
,wap eht yb mih koot sexanauO yllanif nehW
,dnah sih fo kcab eht htiw keehc s’uzlaT dekorts yltfos dna ylneddus dah
”.snoitseuq nwo ruoy ot rewsna eht wonk uoY“
.devil tey namutsiH elihw
ssel dna ssel em detcartsid evah sa“
.ti demusnoc ti sa neve tsap eht otni ti gnixif
.ediserif mraw a dna
,yldlrownu ro larutan rehtie
,denigami era yeht sa selcaro rof era sgniht hcuS
gnivil gnuh nam eht tnaem osla tub
.moor eht tuoba lla sreizarb eht ni gnirehtoms dna gnillems-prahs gnihtemos fo gniredloms eht dna
.reeb fo lwob a erahs dna ,klat dna
.dehgual sexanauO ”!ton yaserad I“
,ffo deppans stfah
.deef ot htuom rehtona fo esuoh reh dir ot dedeen ylerem ehs spahreP
”?hctam suoegatnavda na ekam eh lliw
,deddon dah uzlaT
,thgis fo tuo rohcna thgim pihs a erehw
”.sllah ralucaro eseht fo
.dloheb ot ylevol
ti raew tsum ydobemos dnA
,teef sih ot nesir dah
dlrowrednu eht ot gniyenruoj noom eht tnaem yeht woh
sffilc dezarg-taog eb dluow dnah tfel eht nO
,tsael ta gnik a rof uoy koot I“
wehpen etirovaf taht fi erus ssel won dna ysaenu gats eht
deb elbatrofmoc a rof kool ylerem slaes dna
,ytirailimaf dna noitaitini htiw
,maerd a terpretni nac namow esiw egalliv a ylerus
,erus eb ot ,sdnalsi rehtO“
dah tircO tahW
krad dna dliw gnihtemos—
.aidacrA fo ega nedlog eht ni
,dekil eh sa etal sa peels dluoc eh tnaem thgin ta gnikroW
,dlo worg ot si ti tahw wonk uoY
,tuh elttil sih ni deb eht otni
,ekops uzlaT mohw ot ton wenk eh rof
”.ylleb sih llif dna ,lluh sih hctap
,hsif deird dna daerbtalf rof sdaeb iluzal dna
.dias dah htuom nwo sih tahw eveileb ot elba ecracs dna nekahs
daehrevo erew noom eht sselnu enon ot kaeps dluow elcarO eht rof—
taht dleh eh sa srae sih nihtiw llews neht dluow taht sdipar sselthgiew dna
?eno emas eht saw ti fi rettam ti did—
,siht tuoba gnorw eb ton dluow yeht dnA
.ni smirglip lacitehtopyh ruo wollof woN
,sdrow otni ti tup evah t’ndluoc eh hguoht ,dootsrednu eH
”?he ,uoy ot llaf llew sa yam ti os
,rehtar rO .ees ot
,ytivitca fo lrihw a erutcip mih dnuora nehT
,uzlaT no ytip nekat evah dluow flow dlo eht eb yam ti dnA
,ssalg nekorb fo stnemgarf ynam taerg a ylno si ciasom a syas ohw
”.ereh erusiel tub esle elttil dnif dluow uoy“
,seicehporp tuohtiw od ekam nac
.dias evah dluow namutsiH
,roirraw dewam-rebas sih htiw aes ot deraeppasid dah udhuruK dna
.meht fo htob derewsna uzlaT ”.yrt lliw I“
,ecnartne eht ot tnew eno eht os
,nrobllits eb dluow dlihc txen reh rehtie taht reh dlot dah eh oga snoom owT
mih morf setaname ti fi sa ,sexanauO si
,rehtomdnarg ym taht demaerd I“ .elgae eht syas
.rewsna eht wonk ydaerla ton seod eh hcihw ot
,drib a fo retsnom nettogrof dna lavemirp emos ,ksam taerg A
ecneconni taerg detceffa sexanauO ”?yas uoy ,etariP“
,ytitnedi sih wonk ot seno ylno eht
despalloc flesmih dnuof uzlaT
gnorts os em no emac tI“
ysub peek ot od ot esle elttil saw ereht tub
.yawa dna ssenisub ydlrownu siht htiw enod eb ot tseB
.niarb rieht ni pu delbbub stnemecnuonorp revetahw reviled dna—
.flesym yllohw niw ot naem I“ ,yltneg ,ylwols
1 traP ,floWcaM boR yb
,esruoc fo ,won tuB
”.htneetenin ym eb lliw tsevrah gnimoc sihT“
,snoisivorp rof sretrab mar ehT
,dilos erom dna regral eht mees mih edam ylno ti tcaf ni tuB
,deniatniam evah dluow namutsiH
enodnu sladnas yvaeh htiw
,evah dluow eh spahreP
senots gnippets eht detagivan uzlaT ”,enon si erehT“
tsew tsomrettu eht ni
nugeb dah uzlaT
.ton ti dewohs eh
.snairemmiC raf eht morf sliah ohw
,sreizarb gniredloms eht fo eno revo dehcnuh
,tuo ti desahc ycehporp erofeb
,flow a fo eciov eht ”,wohemoS“
elsI tircO no tuB
enoemos tnaw I taht“
”?he ,ti ni yrolg niw dna
,delims sexanauO
.ylthgit mih gnihctulc
,ti htiw tis dluoc eh litnu
dnatsrednu elcarO eht did
.yrautcnas sih dna sthgieh eht drawot kcab
,sraeps eseht neprahs ot
,syad elttil esoht ni
.seert eht dnoyeb elbisivni
,yltnelis dna ylidaets
.srovaf rieht htob ni neeb deedni dah
,moor eht ssorcA .nac yeht litnU
,werc sih tser thgim niatpac tsenoh na erehw dnalsi na ylno
efil ni htap s’nam a snaem taht uoy llet lliw efiwdlo yna dna
.noitacilppus ni desiar smlap dna daerps smra
.dias evah dluow
.deggurhs god ehT
”,uoy rof tekram eht ot etyloca na dnes dluoc uoY“
.nihc s’raob dlo na fo elbbuts eht ekil edis draobrats eht dedduts ,deirub sdaeh
srehctaw elbamannu eht tnaem osla tub
,reh fo deromane os eb lliw udhuruK dna
,emyhr dna mhtyhr eht tub deniamer gnihton taht os
,yrots trohs tseb rof drawA yraretiL OEL a fo renniw ,floWcaM boR yb ”nwO siH fo etaF oN evaH neM ot etaF htekaepS taht miH
sexanauO ot rehtona evag neht ohw
?ni mih del ohw eno emas ehT
,noitseuq ot nigeb dluow yehT
ytlayor dna htgnerts eht lla mih evig
,sterces sti htiw gninruter dna
”?kees uoy srovaf esohw namow on si ereht dnA“
,mih desserp dah namutsiH
,ssenrettib taerg htiw ,enog dah eh
.edis drawdniw eht ot elbbep hguone-suoip a dda ot—
.flow dlo eht htiw tneps dah eh
”.dneps ot semoc etarip a tahw evas ti fo yna ees ot ekil ton era srednalsi ew
elcaro tseraen eht ot tnes neeb dah uzlaT
,ho dnA .noil eht delims ”,llahs
wets a otni eseht fo lla dessot dah flow ehT .desufnoc
.eye sti saw taht noil eht ot
gnikaeps yltcirts ton si
”.secips hcir dna snenil enif uoy hctef ot pihs a dnes dluoc uoY
,ylluferac yrev ,dias uzlaT
”nwO siH fo etaF oN evaH neM ot etaF htekaepS taht miH teL“
dellac emos mohw
.dniwnu snieks eht lla dna
.gniteerg lausac ni fooh desiarpu na dereffo ehs saw ti mohw ot aedi on dah ehS
,nedrag edis eht ni setanargemop eht gnidnet neeb sah eh nehw
”?niaga hceeps dna knird erahs nac owt ew spahreP“
.yrotsih fo noitnevni eht rof noos oot devil eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.neeserof sa tsuj
,elcarO eniuneg dna eurt a dnA
elcaro remrof eht ,htaed ni nevE
”?dal ,eurt ekops uoY“
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta
,yawa raf os tey hguoht
.tekram ta llub ezirp a yub ot rehtehw gniredisnoc remraf a ekil
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT.drow a ton
edisa ksat revetahw tes dluow eh yad yreve dnA
,htap rieht tsol dah yeht fi ,ecno naht erom
,meht fo eno enimaxe ot raen spets
eelf llahs uoy stnuah erucsbo eseht morF .niav nI
,llits eutats yats ot nehw
,dnuor og ti ekam ot yelrab fo gnipleh doog a htiw—
”!namrehsif a rof siht ekil bubbuh a ees ton dluow uoY
,esruocsid fo enil taht htiw enod ylneddus neeb dah nmautsiH
,yob ,ycehporp yfislaf uoy fI“
.rewop ythgim a ton saw
.rehtegot ligiv no erew uoy fo owt eht nehw
.nwad ta tsuj nugeb yenruoj a fo esimorp ekil gnirrits saw eciov sih fo dnuos eht ho dna
,lliw eerf nwo rieht fo
.taog eht syas ”?naem ti seod tahW
deedni saw ti daeh emosraef a dna—
,neht ,mih enigamI
gnitaews dna dekan
.htorb taem ni gnat yrovas a dna
.drawhtuos dnalsi txen eht no
:kaeps dluow elcaro eht
,eldnips a htiw traeh eht hguorht em decreip
,esruoc fo tub ,hA
skoob yrotsih eht ni ’ollopA‘ dellac eb llew sa thgim ti
.thguorb evah yeht noitseuq eht ksa ot ylno taht dna
,mih dnuora smra s’namutsiH htiw
,dias dah ,ynori htiw levarg ot deird
erohs eht nwod decnalg god ehT
gnuoY saW dlroW eht nehW
.eno ees yeht nehw etarip a swonk“
tsirw eht yb mih ekat neht ,mrarednu dna
,ecnerever fo seltit yna esu ro
I uoy dnif nehT“
.rotatceps esirnus eht
.retniw fo gnissap hcae htiw
,niatrecnu dna esnet
.tserof elohw eht dnatsrednu dna
,taht ta detnioppasid erew namutsiH fI
.deid dah namutsiH ecnis
,gninraeL .evil dna
,hsiveep neeb evah dluow eciov s’flow dlo eht
,ereh neeb dah eh fi
was I“ .ees ot gniht suolirep a saw
.etyloca deksam a morf drow prahs a ta kcab sreggats dna
.segrab erusaert eht morf htlaew on sgnirb namrehsif a rof ,yaN“
,nrut ot nehw wenk
,repeeknrevat eht morf ela fo lwob a detpecca uzlaT ”.reveN ?ereH“
?dnalsi siht evael ot denraey uoy evah“
,etyloca erom on neeb dah
.syad esoht ni ,decitcarp saw elcarO na fo tra eht woh saw taht dnA
,noil eht ees ot mih nihtiw traeh s’uzlaT detsiwt tI
,ria eht no etorw
,eeserof ton od ew neve enutrof doog emoS“
.lla stsaeb gnithgif
,elcarO eht thguos eH
.setyloca ruof sih dna elcaro eht rof deedni laem enif yrev a neeb dah ti dna
,namow a fo tacerbas taerg A
”?ereh derevocsid eb ew lliw ro“
wodniw hgih elgnis a hguorht noom eht ,thgil ylno ehT
”,dneirf ym ,loof a ton ma I“
.detrulb uzlaT ”…t’nod I ,on …I“
,noil a htiw nigeB
.ekaps eldnips eht tahw seviheeb eht ksa oG
,pu nepo dluow seert eht—
,robrah dna nwot fo sthgil eht ot nwod
.mih was tsrif uzlaT sa
.os ssel neve eb dluow ti
,detelpmoc ees ot deen dah I“
,gnarps stsevrah lla
.ekops gniunitnoc erofeb dna
,tey syad wef a saw tI
.der llaf swons yht
,aes eht fo egde eht revo tesnus eht ot deyarts seye s’namutsiH
,mih fo thgis hctac uoy sa tsuj
.taorht sih ni esir lworg a tlef dah uzlaT
,nwo sih ssel elttil a emoceb traeh sih tlef uzlaT yad yrevE
,retteb uoy wonk ot ksa thgim I fI“
wonk niaga reven tirips ruoy yam neht“
.eeht no skcab rieht nrut sniatnuom tsedlo ehT
,evah ot thguo noil a
,thgilnus fo hcuot eht llew swonk
,ton od snairotsih eht tahw tuB .gnorw
,ereh robrah ekam I fI“ .emit ni tsuJ
,deksa dah sexanauO ti fo eceip eht tsael ta ,etaF
ereh meht thguorb dah ohw srolias eht erehw
,ylyls god gnuoy eht ta decnalg namutsiH ”,evah uoy tuB“
”,gniht tsal eht saw tI“
.eerf gnihgual ti tes ot nruter uoy erE
.ereht neeb eh dah
.dniw aes looc tnatsnoc eht ni gnirettug pmal lio na
sraep erew ereht“
nekops dah eh hcihw fo
,raeh ot detcepxe dah eh revetahW
.shgiht erab sih neewteb tser ot
”?tsewhtron eht fo nalc eht ot egeis yal I nehw yrotciv ees I llahS“
.thguorb dah eh noitseuq eht ksa ot taht dna
,ogniD mailliW yb uoy rof daer ,flowcaM boR yb
,noziroh tsae eht dnoyeb sniatnuom eht morf noitargim wols sti ekam dluow separg fo noitavitluc eht ere
,esu hcum ees ton did tI
.yleritne tsol saw traeh sih taht detpecca uzlaT
thgin fo ssenkrad eht ni daeha raeh dluow yehT
,tnemevom ysae rof dedivid dnik eht
.yenruoj a htrow saw
,nrevat rellams s’dnalsi eht fo repeek won ,armikirA
.mih fo ees reve ew tsal eht eb lliw taht dna
god eht ta elims ot hguone gnol
reeb fo lwob a ro
”,eciojer ,neht yhW“
,htuom sih denepo
.hcaet ot tnaem ton dah eh riapsed evissap eht detaicerppa evah dluow rehcaet sih eb yam tI .ereht neeb eh dah
daeh rieht tuoba dehtaerw ssenkrad dna ekoms
etulas eldi na denruter uzlaT
.yad eht ni dekil eh revetahw od
.ecaf s’etarip eht ssorca dehsalf feiler desirpruS
nus eht fo thgil eht ni dna
.emit ot emit morf desirprus eb ot sdeen elcarO na neve
dniheb lwahs reh tfel sah rehtomdnarg yhT
,deltrats etylocA eht dna
”.ssenisub ym tuoba eb tsum I
.decalper lla neeb dah yeht
.remmus htnet sih fo tsdim eht ni—
,nrecnoc lla mih morf ekat tub
elcarO eht namutsiH
,elbat eht ta ecalp s’rehtomdnarg reh ni flesreh gnirutcip fi sa
,uzlaT dehcuot dah nam oN ”.em stnaw ohw
,rof dekool eb ot saw ti ega eht ta slrig rof ssendnof on dewohs eh was ehs spahrep
,ecno tub kaeps ot mih dnammoc ot
,niav ni redisnoc dluow eh tuB
”,ssenisub sih swonk ohw elcaro nA“
.slatrom fo secnarbmemer eht ni eman on sah
,nrecnoc rof emit on saw ereht tuB
,delkraps seye ’sexanauO
.eciov sih morf raef fo elbmert a peek yllohw ton dluoc eh tuB
,deksa evah dluow namutsiH
osla did god gnuoy eht woh
,redluohs sih desserp setyloca sih fo enO
,mih sdrawot gnillor erutuf eht leef dluow uzlaT
,elcaro rednarg a eh erew
.pu detfil seye sih
,namow a htiw nial reven evah I“
nialp dial daor sih sees ohw nam ehT
,dias evah dluow namutsiH
,eb yad eno dluow eamuC ro nuilI ro
deb yht ni gninrub eil llahs tnepres ehT
,robal gnipahs-dlrow rieht ta sdog laidromirp sa demahsanu dna
,semulov txen eht ni krow sih rof kool ot erus eB
ksa ot ereht ton saw namutsiH lufetarg saw eh ,peels otni
”?egufer efas a su rof niamer ti lliw“
,eb dluoc uoy taht lla uoy ekasroF .erom oN
”?dnats uoy nac ,esaelP“
hguone derutam dna esor seripme taerg eht erofeb
,reh htiw yawa lias lliw eH ?ton yhw
,dluow eh dias dah namutsiH sa tsuj
.thgilnoom fo tfahs eht ni dnats dna
,ksam eht fo edisni eht tuoba elttar ot
ytilauq elbaton tsom s’elsI tircO fo elcaro eht saw ’tseraen‘ rof—
,ecno ylno kaeps ot
”?traped ot tuoba eb thgim uoy gniwonk“
retne ot dlot era yeht tub
.sksam rieht dniheb ,kool deirrow a derahs setyloca tseraen owt ehT
”,evil ton did I dalg ma I“ ”.nam dlo
flesmih dekooc reven tsomla namutsiH dna—
”,deedni hcum yrev raef I ,yob ,hcuM“
,ereht neeb elcaro remrof eht dah
”.em stnaw nam a nehw wonk ot hguone wonk I“
ytivitca fo mrots eht hguorht yaw sih ekam ot emit emos uzlaT koot tI
eltrats meht eeS
,elbaraebnu gnimoceb morf
,sebor suonygordna gniliart eht ffo pils dluoW
”.og dluow I erehwon fo wonk I“
deciton erew yeht retfa tsuj
,pihs eht otno drow a tuohtiw mih dellup
,yaw sti ekam ot eno ylno eht ,dlot selat dna
.sih ot gnulc spil s’etarip eht fo etsat ehT
?em htiw htaerb taht ekat
?dettimda eb ot nevig dah yeht tahw dnoyeb ,smla lanoitidda na rof ,spahreP
,esruoc fo ,mih evig lliw I hcihW
daorssorc eht ta senots fo elip eht ta deppots uzlaT
”…mih peek ot hsiw uoy esuaceb
elcaro eht saw ti woh dna—
,tekram eht ni yad yreve mih tem uzlaT semiteB
,ksam yvaeh eht gnicnalaB
,ees nac won eh moor eht tuoba lla era yehT
,won yb teef sih ot mih depleh evah dluow namutsiH
,htaeneb nam eht ot
.did eh tuB .ton did tsoM
,gninraw on dah uzlaT yhw si taht eb yam tI
drehpehs tneconni na naht serac erom on dah eh fi sa
,niaga tuo meht rehsu dluow—
,dloh eht otni serots gnivaeh lla ylerem ro
,etarip eht teem ot
,gurd emos saw ti yas dluow ,gurhs dluow
worp reppoc dehsinrub eht dna
”’.dlo‘ flesmih llac
”,niaga tsap eht no gnillewd era uoY“
,dias evah dluow namutsiH
,emoc thgim snoisiv revetahw taht
esnecni fo xim terces rettib eht htaerb sih htiw gnitsaT
,spahrep ,sretsulb roirraw ehT
uoy rehtehw rof erac yna evah ot sa
edalb derih a gniraeb ,yldetcepxenu
.htaerb werd tey eh ees ot deveiler ,yltneg
sexof dna star eht ro
”?neht ,netfo set arip htiw edart evah uoY“
,mih dniheb enots nrow-dniw eht no dednuos toof erab a fo pets eht nehw tuB
.ereht dehcaeb pihs rednels eht ta
.delkcuhc flow dlo eht
.taht ekil dennirg eh revenehw
dlot yeht yrots elohw eht ees dna
elixe dna ecnirp htob saw eh hcihw fo modgnik ehT .gniK etariP
ti fo eerf mih dellup
”.rewsna eht wonk ton seod eh hcihw ot
”…hsif ynnut dna eseehc tlas dna
dnah ni ksat rehtona dah noil eht yad yrevE
,moor siht ni eno ylno eht ton saw eH
,tsurt I ,srednalsi eht fo ynA“ .dias god eht
,neesnu eb tey ,raen os
.reh yap dluoc god eht erofeb yawa deltsub dna
?sterces dna ecivres ym ekasroF
,htaerb dellif-emuf
,emit tsrif eht rof
?mih morf sterces evah dluoc nam tahW ?ton eh saw
,tsap eht no llewd ot steg uzlaT fI
,nwad erofeb tsuj ekowa eh nehw dnA
.taorht sih ni thguac dah htaerb s’uzlaT
,ydaer eb ot dedeen I
.nalp ot elba neeb evah dluow eh desseug uzlaT naht
,robrah eht morf yawa edorts uzlaT
.esae ta yltcefrep naht ssel
.deb yna naht gnitrofmoc erom demees ruf taht nopu gniyal fo ytilibissop eht ho dna
daeh s’uzlaT ni thguoht tsal eht saw sihT
.devoleb sih peek ot ti dneb ro etarutluda ot deen on neeb dah erehT
,yad yreve stae eno sa hcum
,esae ta swap erab dna
.dednet ecno dah eh setanargemop sseltiurf eht htaeneb
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.serutsap reppu eht drawot staog fo dreh a gnivird wos a morf
,maws daeh s’uzlaT .taht ton saw ti
”!kcab ti reffo I riaf ylno s’ti ,yhw ,ytilatipsoh dnab roop ym dereffo sah elsi riaf ruoy fI
,tserof mid eht ni daeha ,ees noos ot ylno
evisnep taog eht
,derepsihw noil eht ”,thginoT“
,sserieh na spahrep rO
,rewsna na gniggeb erew eh fi erusnu neeb daH .dias dah uzlaT
,deb otni espalloc flesmih tel uzlaT sa dnA
,draeh evah ton lliw uoY
uzlaT dellac god gnuoy a ylnO
”?eno taht no gnidoorb neeb uoy evah gnol woH“
ruoh eht fo ssenkrad eht yb tsugua dna
,elcarO eht dedeen sexanauO dnA ?ton eh did
mraw eht dima ydaets daeh sih peek ot gnithgif dna
seirutnec nezod a naht erom eb dluow tI
rettucdoow a gnikees ro
,meht htiw degrahc eh erofeb
,reeb fo ytnelp ,ylleb lluf a
,sreizarb eht morf emoc evah dluow
,sevlesmeht ereh pots ot skniht meht fo eno a reven sA
,leenk ot mih rof neddibrof saw tI .dias dah uzlaT
.derepsihw uzlaT ”,hguone gnoL“
,ksam drib yvaeh-pot eht ffo llup
thguoht eh rof ,ton meht detiderc tsrif eh dna
ti htiw nrut ,ti htiw dnats
.dedaehthgil mih edam s’reizarb eht ni gnihtemos dnA
.keerc ysub a wolf dluow ereht
dnah rehto sih nI
,sniar gnirps eht gnirud
,nam wollef a naht
,yrugua ro nemo emos saw ereht spahrep
erew ereht sropav tahw dnA
noitseuq a deksa evah ton dluow
:srevol fo elbaivne tsom taht fo ynapmoc eht ni snrevat eht ni tas
,won sraey neetriht eseht daed
.rebmahc renni na ot
.emoceb dah etaf fo syaw eht egnarts woh no kniht ot
.ecneuqesnoc on fo dleh eh
.etylocA eht derepsihw
”.ereh ,hguone emosdnah ,llew
,gninrom etal saw tI
sllac srallip s’tesnus eht nopu enorht yhT“
.reeb fo lwob sih deniard dna
noitom taht tfel dah noil eht tub
.eert gif eht ni gnignah em tfel dna
,hturt ni ,dnalsi eht no daorssorc ylno eht—
worromot taht waserof dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
,mih fo gnus erew deedni scipe hguoht dnA
,erew ro—era yeht sa ton
,tey os ro yrutnec-flah a eb dluow tI
sehsub etanargemop eht dna
,taf dna yenoh dna nroc ylno si ekac laicifircas a syas ohw
.kcab eht tuo yaw sih elbmuf dluow elcaro eht
.stirips lufegnev dna daed eht fo sedahs fo sepahs eht koot dlrowrednu eht morf sropav cinohthc erehw
”.traped ot raeb dluoc I ere
seert dima dnats yam retnuh esiwdoow a sa
nwod dna pu uzlaT dekool dna
”,snoitcartsid emas eht llA“
tircO fo elsI ehT   2 fo
”.deirt d’I fi detsiser evah t’ndluoc I taht
kcab gniog redisnoc dluow yeht nehw tsuj dnA
,epip gnitnuah a no deyalp
,roreuqnoc eb dluow uohT
.SFHF eht morf elbaliava osla
,sredluohs sih ssorca kaolc a erow noil eht
,ylluf nam rehto eht hcuot ot dnah sih fo noitom tsellams eht ylno koot ti ”,wonk I dnA“
nedrag edis ynit eht ni
,denethgil pets sih ,yaw eno eht
,ogniD mailliW yb daeR
,ezorf dna denethgiarts ydaerla ton uzlaT daH ”?dal he
.hsas sih ot nwes sdaeb nedlog gnilgnad eht fo eno eerf gniggut yb syap eh mohw
,flesreh thgiserof fo hcuot a dah ehs spahreP
,rotaro eht htap eht nwod
?mih erofeb ssenkrad eht ni devom ytinivid revetahw erofeb elbmuh mees ot tnaem eh spahrep rO
,daeh sih koohs uzlaT
,setir eht dniheb sgninaem fo edutitlum eht tub ,setir eht tsuj ton gninraeL
”,ereh gnik on evah eW“
,reve sa ycerces ot nrows sa tsuj erew setyloca rehto ehT
,desiugsid eb ot tnaem eh spahreP .hguor dna bard
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb
.mih fo draeh dah I dna
.tuoba gniklat saw namutsiH tahw aedi on dah dah uzlaT ”…I“ ”?ecnis detsat
,og ot esor uzlaT sa teef sih ot dehcterts sexanauO
rebma htiw gnurts secalkcen gnidart ro ,tsam wen a rof
”,uzlaT em llac yehT“ ”.esruoc fo
ton evah I hcihW
,robrah eht ni ylbatrofmoc dehcaeb
,ot derac eh fi won saw ehs erehw dias evah dluoc eh elcaro sa spahrep—rehtom siH
gnihtyna dias evah ton dluow eh yhw si taht eb yam tI
”.elcarO eht kees ohw esoht evas lla yb dekoolrevo si tircO tub
,ega gniyrram a fo si zummaT gnuoY“
,yawa tpews dah edit sti sgniht eht gnoma neeb dah namutsiH
.tsrif ekops etarip eht rof
.rotatcepS esirnuS eht
dnah eht htaeneB
.dlog naht eugnot eht no
,sworra wef a naht erom dna
”.naem uoy tahw s’taht fi
,skcarc eldnips ehT
,nevig m’I rewsna yldneirfnu na s’ti fi
.tseuqnoc fo tsevrah s’nosaes txen no gnidoorb ,tnaryt emos enigami su teL
,robrah eht ot deklaw efil ni devol d’eh god eht sa
,detsuahxe dna gnipmil
,yrautcnas eht ot kcab ti ekam ot emit hguone ylerab tub dah uzlaT
emac reven taht sknaht evisuffe rof ,gninihs seye
.tneserp erem ot deldniwd dah erutuf taht
gniyashtoos sih wohemos taht
,evocla neddih a ni epip gnitnuah eht deyalp dah eh
,rehtael denehguot fo tlik a mih evig
.ti fo dlot erew selat oN
.elsI tircO fo elcarO eht ot
gnilpmud eseehc A
slias deroloc norffas eht htiw
”?od I fi tahw oS“ ”.lausu naht erom“
,sduolc eht ni ,srats eht ni
,meht deksa eh erofeb snoitseuq ot srewsna eht wonk ot nageb eH .did yeht tahw
,dluow ti dias dah namutsiH sa tsuj
”!geb tsum I snodrap dnasuoht a s’ti ,yhW“
,rebmemer dluoc yrautcnas eht esrev revetahw gniziromeM
noitseuq a sksa ylerar“
ylsuonimo meht drawot nrut dluow elcaro ehT !dloheB—
,srae s’uzlaT dekorts yltneg sexanauO
,seye suoirepmi dna
ygolohtna gninniw drawa eht morf
.ereht dnuof eb ot erew sehcir oN
ollopA yb dessessop sevlesmeht eveileb neht dluow ohw renoititcarp a ni ecnart ecudni ot
,rebmemer ot dnim sih dekcarw dah god eht ”…saw ereht ,oN“
.niaga klaw ot lliw eht dnuof teef sih erofeb elihw a ecnelis ni doots uzlaT ”.hturt kaeps dna
.elcarO eniuneg dna eurt a saw
,cinut s’god eht denetsafnu yltneg sexanauO
,rae sih ni ylsuonimo derepsihw evah dluow namutsiH
doolb s’traeh esohw morf ecifircas sa eert dercas a no
?nialp eht fo seitic eht gnoma yob a tey saw I nehw
,yaw rehto eht ti tfel
.maerd gnilbuort a fo noitaterpretni na gnikees
hcneb enots eht no flesmih tas
,neht emoC .eltsub siht dima erusiel fo htaerb a ekat ohw
,hcihw fo tlih eht htiw
,emoc dah pihs eht emit eht yB
.yas ot tahw redisnoc ot emit mih evag tI .doog saw sihT
.sdoow eht drawot pu nem sih fo emos derutseg sah eh
,esoppus I ,yadot snairotsiH
ihpleD fo selebyC eht sa suoigitserp ro suomaf os ton erew ti fi neve
.gnicitcarp osla tub ,eya
”,deen evah nem dna pihs ym nehw
,repeeknrevat eht yb tuo thguorb
,robrah llams eht ot emoc dluow yehT
,yponac nenil eht rednu dial erew snoihsuc erehw
,od ew tahw rof emoc ohw esohT“
pihs duorp eht fo
,tiaw yeht neht dnA .gats eht syas
tsehc s’sexanauO nwod wap s’uzlaT dael dna
reteews si neerg tuB
,htaed fo setag ehT otnu
,enod saw ti reveyhW
won yb yawyna dna
gninepo retteb a saw taht dnA
deb egairram a otni yaw nwo sih dnif nac wehpen raed s’eno ylerus
.dnuor yaw thgir eht
…deedni won krad si ti rof
.dnim sih ytpme dna lliw sih neffits ot hguone devorp thguoht tahT .uzlaT ton ,yas ot dah elcarO eht tahw rettam on
,denruter sesnes sih
.mih ni sngis emos nees dah—ton did eh tub
wap s’noil eht fo noitom emas ehT
,srae sih dekrep noil ehT ”?elcarO“
,gniees neeb dah eh ezilaer ot nugeb dah
”.flesym ti rewsna ot elba eb yam I
”?em fo evah uoy dluow tahW“
.ekops eh mohw ot saw ti ohw laever thgim taht rof
.noitasucca na gnikam ro
.gniylper ni esoprup on was uzlaT .desuma yltaerg
dog erutluv a ekil
noitseuq a sksa ylerar elcaro nA
”?eil a kaeps uoy draeh ecno reven evah I taht“
,spahrep ,saw tahT
,niatnuom eht fo edis siht no llew worg ton did yeht rof tiurf tes reven
.rewsna eht wonk ydaerla ton did eh hcihw ot
,pihs eht fo stib esoht riaper ot sretneprac skees xebi eht
,gnipeels dna gnikaw ,tnemom yrevE .ecitnerppa tub
knalf sih fo epahs eht erolpxe
.ycehporp rieht gniraeh no worros ro
”,robrah edam dah setarip on nehw su was tub uoy fI“
”?deedni ysehporp saw tahT“
,yad yreve reraelc
.hcae su erofeb daor a si emitefil A“
,ela fo lwob sih dehsinif eh sa
.eerf si eh rof ,ytingid lla dna
,sniatruc kcalb hguorht ni nehT
,setyloca tnelis-nrows sih fo eno ediseb tsuj
.yrautcnas eht eb dluow dnah thgir eht no tuB
”,yob ,ti si yhw dnA“
,elcaro sa ecalp sih nekat dah uzlaT dna
,demees noil ehT ”.hA“
,nekorb erew srao lareveS
.snaem eert gif eht tahw eldnips eht ksa oG ,rO
,dekaorc uzlaT ”,did I“
.emit hcae regnol elttil a
,niaga ecaf sih desiar noil eht nehw ylno dnA
retnecipe sti ta dna
.emas eht dekaolc dna dedooh lla dna
radec a gnillef tuoba ees ot
,pmal a fo kciw eht ekil erutuf eht nwod denrub tneserp eht woH .gnola lla
.yadot enon fo wonk I ,rehtar
,yb emoc lliw pihs gnidart a ,noom a nihtiW
.ehtab ot frus eht otni
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,saep kcihc kcab thguorb uoY“
meht dima dnats ot woh tub
,ssefnoc dluow etyloca eht
.lla ta ereht elcaro on saw ereht litnu
,namelbon lacirotaro na rO
.setyloca eht fo rehtona tsuj saw uzlaT
,drabbacs nrow a ni drows ytsurt a dna
,ekam ot desu rehtom ym
”?raew uoy od sraey ynam woH“
htaed fo setag eht ta nrets dna sselnoitom dnats ohw
.mih evol ot gnol evah ton lliw uoY“
.ton ti degdelwonkca eh
,ngiapmac ylekil-ssel-won a revo
.nageb ylurt efil sih ,did eh nehw dnA
”.bmal fo tib doog a dna ,steeb ,keel
.snmuloc roop sekam naidisbO
dereviled dah ti ynitsed fo tsiwt tahw fo ron
.tops eht no esrev otni etallesset ot ytiliga eht evah dluow eugnot sih
,seirtsepat htiw gnuh llaw a ekil
,snmuloc naidisbo fo ecalap sselthgil a saw ti demialc ti draeh evah I
,spahrep rO .ekaw eht ot
.smra sih otni nwod dna
,niaga kaeps ot ton saw eh ,emit ni tsuj
,yrenif ylecnirp naht rehtaR
.detrap dah selzzum rieht nehw ,deksa uzlaT
,sepols reppu eht no sradec eht gnoma deklaw uzlaT
.ton did eh eb yam tI
.elcaro eht detisiv sexanauO ere
.rehtie ,muihplis hcum yrev os evah ton did tircO ,yawynA
,noil eht ediseb taes a koot god eht
dnif dna peels fo shtnom neetriht rof kees oG
,retaw hserf fo sraj sllif erutluv eht
.siht si syad rettal dloc eseht ot
!yas ot elbissopmi ,hA
ta senots gnilip htrow
?saw eh naht regral gnihtemos otni mih edam stnemrag gnilaecnoc esohw ,eh saw
.edit gniwollaws-dnalsi taerg a ekil
.ereh niamer ot efas erew ti gnol woh em llet thgim elcaro eht taht
”.niatfeihc a rof neve hguone klof ton evah ew ,ytsenoh lla ni“
”,llew yrev wonk uoY“
?wonk ot kees uoy ti si tahW“
.wehpen etirovaf sih rof egairram suoegatnavda na gnikees
.dneirf ym ,traeh ruoy retfa ton ksa I ,salA“
taht nwonk evah dluow eh eb yam ti rof
riah a tsuj saw noisnet eht nehw dnA
detniauqca era sepirts yerg-elbbep tcnitsidni eht
.gnihtaerb nwo rieht tlef yeht sa ylerus sa drager s’elcaro eht fo thgiew eht tlef ton dah ,smirglip fo sraey eht lla fo ,eno a ton teY ?enots knalb fo seye htiw ,erats ti dluoc woh tey ,erats dluow tI .dlrowrednu eht morf nesir
.tekram eht
,esnesnon ti fo hcum
s’uzlaT tuB .nwonknu eb
,tfel smirglip ruo retfa taht si ,wonk ton dluoc
.hcnew gnilliw a dna
.elsI tircO no efil sih erofeb elttil yrev derebmemer uzlaT
,deggurhs uzlaT ”,rednalsi nA“
,devirra tsrif I nehw ,em desivda enoemos ,oN
evoc a rof tsaoc eht gnituocs erew nem sih—
?ecnereffid eht wonk ot saw ohw dnA
,efil reh tsoc dluow ti fo gnihtrib eht ro
”,emit taht lla ni dnA“
”,taht od ot efas eb lliw ti gnol woH“
.sevael gnilrufnu eht sllif gnirps ni pas gnisir a ekil
.sedalbredluohs s’uzlaT neewteb sregnif dloc tup llits taht fo yromem ehT
,koot eh tahw saw ti os ,modeerf saw
.sgniht hcus eveileb ton dluow I tuB
”?wodiw suorepsorp oN ?nortam pmulp oN
sreizarb eht ni denrub
.raeppaer dluow yks eht dna
sdoow eht ni rewolf wolley elap a ylno deniamer ti os
shtims skees eopooh eht
.rehtraf og ot thguoht reven dah dna
nam a hcus ton saw sexanauO
.ton dluoc noil eht dna
gniyfirret ot deifingam
.dlrow-flah eht fo seiretsym eht ot sdael
.ris deronoh ,tem lleW“
.gniksa era yeht si ti ohw ees neve tonnac yehT
,did eh tahw did flow dlo eht woh
.devirra mirglip txen eht litnu
ecaf sih dnuora ksam nworb-hsa na ot denekrad ,taoc eldnirb—
dah eb ot yruxul ylno eht
,egalliv eht ot htap eht nwod yaw eht no spahrep
.ereht ecnerefretni s’etaf reffus ton ll’I
,gnidiar ym morf ,ereh nruter I fi
,thgin eht rof dekcol erew srood eht dna
,ereht elihw a desuap eH
,robrah eht tuoba deretsulc sgnidliub eht dehcaorppa uzlaT sa
,muihplis evarc ot
,elsI tircO fo sdradnats eht yb tsael ta
,emit a retfa ,god ehT
redael raw denosaes a ylerus—
”.em dnif ot erehw uoy llet nac
,desoppus eh ,setyloca eht fo emoS
,daeh sih koohs evah dluow namutsiH
,nekops dah uzlaT eceip eht
,elbmeser yeht sduolc dekaerts-mrots eht htiw
,tnemom a tsuj rof
.sradec gnihgis eht hguorht htap gnidniw eht pu yaw rieht ekam
.edis rieht no neeb dah
,ylsuoituac ,dias uzlaT
.suonimun dna lufewa ssel erew sdoow eht
meht ksa ot denrael dah eh ecno
.llew sa od ew riaf ylno sit
ylnellus elgae eht—
delbuortnu sa sniamer rehtegot efil ’sexanauO dna uzlaT fi woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.ereht thguof neeb dah selttab taerg oN
,elcarO eht gnikees ton emoc uoy fI“
,seenk sih no sexanauO was eh
swov sih morf desaeler neeb dah eh dna
rehtorb sih htiw namrehsif a eb ot
?tnasaep eht erom
,thgin a fo seenk s’udhuruK neewteb detropsid“
.epoh yeht sa etaf yb
.niaga os enod evah dluow eh
hguone esolc gnihtemos tsael ta ro—
ees ot evil tey yam uoy ega dlo liarf dnA
gninrom a fo deb sih demraw dna ,eyA
,elcarO saw mih gnitnemrot flow dlo siht …neht tuB
,mih dessik etarip eht ”,tahT
namutsiH ”,erom evah dluoc uoY“ .dluoc eh nehw
sreizarb yrautcnas eht morf ekoms fo slruc eht snrettap eht ni
.hctef ot setyloca dnes ot mih rof seiruxul erew ereht fi
,sdoow eht ni snretnal eht til dah eH
.elcarO eht kees ot emac sexanauO erofeb flesmih mlac dna ,ksam dna sebor sih nod
,htaerb sih no etsat s’flow dlo eht htiw
suht mih devol dah ,mih dleh dah
mih llif etaf tlef dna
,derewsna dah namutsiH
,ekops eh sa srae s’god gnuoy eht delzzun evah dluow eh tub
”,tsal ere gninrom a ,tekram eht ot tnew uoy nehw ,woN
modsiw s’elcaro eht fo gninaem peed eht
”,wonk uoy did woH“
sdnalsi elttil eht gnoma dog elttil a ot enirhs rehto yna ekil saw ti ylekil eroM
wonk dluoc dnim latrom on sterces gnipeek
,wollef emosdnah a ro
”.hctaw sselpeels gnol retfa
,tsaerb sih no daeh
,niatpac ,em esucxe lliw uoy fI
.yenruoj eht fo ssenilenol eht dna