,xoF revliS eht fo ytreporp eht won si ograc ruoY
,seires snogarD fo ynitseD sih htiw cigam dna snogard fo rohtua eht ,setaoC .R.F.J yb
,seye sih revo nwod deppird ti sa yllaicepse
,temleh sih edisnI
.sdnah devolg sih ni daeh sih dleh siH
,derehtet gnieb fo ecnedifnoc eht gnileeF
,epip eht otno gnidloh syawla dnah eno htiW
.tuh eht tsniaga pmuht duol a saw ereht erofeb
.yldam smra rieht gnivaw ,pu depmuj lla
.temleh sih no nottub eht ni desserp dna
.retlehs eht tih gnihtemos draeh I“
.htrim ni pu til seye reh neht tub
.ti ekam ylefas ot elba eb t’ndluow yeht neht
,ecalp otni kcab rae sih hctarcs ot deirt ordnaeL ,ylevitcnitsnI
,sreucser rieht teem ot ssorca nar ylkciuq
.dioretsa enitsirp-ecno eht no kcor fo sdrahs derettacs eht ffo detcarfer dna
ecaps ytpme ni delbbarcs dnah eerf siH
.noisiced eht edam evah dluohs I“
.egneveR s’rorepmE eht draoba emocleW .snaem lla yB“
.seenk sih koohs tcapmi eht sa gnicniw
,drawrof spets fo elpuoc a koot ehS
.smra sih devaw dna
,denaorg eh ”,on on on on hO“
kcor eht ffo detehcocir revirdwercs elgnis a sa ylsselpleh dehctaw eH
.srotpecer etsaw s’tius eht yb detcelloc saw ti erofeb ydob sih nwod delkcirt tI
,deb tseraen eht otno nwod knus ordnaeL ”.dne eht litnU“
.efas eB .neht thgirlA“
,kcor eht ffo decnuob dna kcab llef eH
.hcum oot gnisu t’nerew yeht erus ekam ot
.hguoht kcab gnimoc eb ot gniog erew yeht erus saw eH
,enod saw ti nehw htaerb peed a koot eH
.yawyna enog dna emoc dah emoctuo krad taht rof ytinutroppo fo wodniw ehT
.tuo flesmih dehcterts eh hcum woh rettam on
.depacse negyxo suoicerp fo duolc oN .dekael gnihtoN
.dah yeht tahw htiw od ekam ot evah dluow eH
,dekrow ti fi tuB
,krow wols saw tI
,esirnus eht hctaw ot emit hguone tsuJ
.teg dluoc yeht pleh eht lla dedeen eH
.taht rof nwod eb d’I“ .dekrims nellE
,nworb fo sedahs erew starats tsom elihW
.noitcartxe dennalp rieht litnu evivrus ot meht fo owt neve rof tfel negyxo hguone t’nsaw erehT
.kcab flesmih llup ot deirt eh sa
,boj riaper degdob eht ta derats eH
.tuh dna knat eht ot detcennoc yleruces ytterp eb ot deraeppa ti tub ,epip eht fo dne rehtie ot dekool eH
,yratnemidur erew yehT
.ti nopu dekool dah yeht emit tsrif eht ot tnereffid saw noziroh eht dna
,noisufnoc ni srae reh dekcilf dna deknilb eitsirhC
.meht dellik dah ecifircas a tpecca ot ecnatculer siH
,tcatni demees slenap ralos ehT
.mih raeh t’ndluoc namuh eht esac ni tsuj ,emit emas eht ta ylsuorogiv gniddon
.sruoh net rehtona rof ehtaerb ylbatrofmoc ot ria hguone evah dluow yeht neht
.rehto hcae tsgnoma deklat dna
,noitisop elbatrofmoc erom a otni liat sih elggirw dna yrt ot kcab sih gnitsiwT
olis gnimaelg eht ffo enohs thgiL
.dne rehtie morf ti evomer ot elba eb d’eh detbuod eH
”,emoc d’yeht uoy dlot I“
ylppus elohw rieht tsol evah dluoc yeht esle ro ,knat eht tih yltcerid t’ndah ti
.mih dniheb gnidnats nellE ees ot denrut ordnaeL
”?od ew od tahw oS“
.dah eh lla saw ti tub ,laedi t’nsaw tI
.kael negyxo na evah eW“
.rof depoh evah dluoc starats emos naht erom saw tI
,derehtetnu sloot rewop eht esu ot tnaw t’ndid eH .decamirg eH
,gnivom htuom reh ees dluoc eh rosiv reh hguorhT
.rae ot rae morf dennirg eH
,dioretsa eht fo epahs eht degnahc dah stroffe gninim riehT
.tsrif sevlesmeht yojne dluow yeht tsael ta tub
”.taht hguorht enog evah dluohs su fo enoN
.dias eitsirhC ”,ehtaerb ton ...tsuj t’nac eW
.kcab flesmih llup ot dah eH
,ecaps otni ffo taolf ot detrats dna
.reh raeh ot deen t’ndid eH
.rotacinummoc sih rof delbmuf ylbmun sregnif sih dna
.ylthgils daeh sih koohs dna
,raew ot sehtolc rehto on dah yehT
”.ruot eht uoy evig em teL
.ordnaeL fo daeha deppets ehS
,noisiv sih raelc dna yrt ot semit wef a deknilb eH
.ereht tuo luferac eB“
?od ew od tahw lleW“ ”.tihs lleW“
deb eht revo tuo dehcterts ydob dekan reH
.tibro s’dioretsa eht fo tuo esle gnihtyna kconk yllatnedicca t’ndid eh erus gnikam
.ordnaeL ,ereh er’eW“
,tuat elbac gnirehtet reh llup ot tuo deppets ehS
,tsehc sih ni ylduol gnipmuht traeh sih htiW
.edistuo og ot su fo eno rof noisiced thgir eht neeb evah t’ndluow tI
.meht rof dedivorp neeb dah taht stik loot eht tuo dellup dna
”.temleh ruo sevomer dna edistuo seog su fo enO“
.htnom gniniamer eht tsal ot ria eraps hcum evah t’ndid yeht wenk eH
.seires nrobeR eht ni sepop ecaps dna starats fo dna
”ykS ehT nI sthgiL“
.ordnaeL ta nwod delims eH
.derepsihw ordnaeL
guh eht fo tuo kcab dellup eH
.tius reh fo eerf elggirw ot detrats ehs sa
.slareniM nosretsaM fo ytreporp eht regnol on saw eH
esirprus ni dekwauqs eh ,tuh eht dehcaer ordnaeL sA
”?taht s’tahW“ .deksa ehs
,lla ti hguorht tuB
.egamad yna ees t’ndluoc eH
.mih fo tnorf ni nellE ees ot niaga nepo dekrej seye siH
.ertem negyxo eht ta yllufnruom derats eH
.ruf sih hguorht delriws ylwols sregnif reH
muucav ytpme eht tsniaga elbisiV
.olis eht morf yawa sertem derdnuh a dnal ot
,guh a otni mih dellup ehS
.ecafrus eht ot nwod kcab mih dellup yeht pleh s’eitsirhC htiw dna
.trohs syad ruof lacitirc esoht rof meht troppus ot ria hguone revocer ot elba reven erew yeht tub
”,taht deen ton did I epoh I“
.pmar eht pu starats owt rehto dna namuh eht dewollof ordnaeL
.no eveels rebbur eht edils dluoc eh os trapa epip eht fo sevlah owt eht tneb ylluferac eH
.temleh sih edisni flesmih ot erows eh ”,tihs tihs tihS“
.sdnah devolg s’tarats eht naht retteb erew yeht tub
kcolria eht deretne eh erofeB
.desolc seye sih dezeeuqs ordnaeL
.dehcaorppa pihs eht sa rethgirb tog yks eht ni sthgil ehT
ylwols os evom ot demees gnihtyrevE
.ylsuovren liat sih dekcilf eH .dias ordnaeL
.tuh llams rieht fo tnorf eht dnuora nekorb gnihtyna t’nsaw ereht dna
.eciohc hcum evah t’ndid eh tub
.deb eht yb deniamer ehs ,yllufknahT
”,rehtegot eb lla ll’ew tsael ta tuB“
.nottub rotacinummoc eht rof gnilbbarcs sregnif
.gel thgir sih nwod gnihctiwt liat sih fo pit eht
,derevocer eb ot dedeen spahrep noitautis eht taht gnisingoceR
,hcum oot sevlesmeht trexe t’ndid yeht fI
,tnemnorivne ytivarg laminim eht ni nur ot tluciffid saw tI
.seilppus rieht revo skcehc lausu sih nur ot detrats ordnaeL
.epip eht hguorht tuc ot detrats ylwols eh erofeb
,tfihs yreve fo trats eht tA
.ti xif dna og ot hguone mih rehtob t’ndid ti tub
,rehtegot tneserp neeb dah yeht snoisacco wef eht nI
.eciohc rehto on dah eH
.niaga temleh eht devomer eh sa
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?esol ew did hcum woH“
.ograc rieht tisoped ot olis eht ot kcab nruter dluow gninim starats owt eht
.yrruh ot dah eh wenk eh tub
”.taht od ot gniog si eno oN“
,sepor rehtet eht otno dleh dnah enO
.noitca neddus otni desinavlag
.doog rof sloot rieht nwod ot dediced dah eerht eht ,gniniamer ria elttil os htiW
;eid dluow yeht neht
.pmar eht nwod deklaw dna kcolria eht morf degreme erugif elgnis A
sdnah sih htiw epip eht dleh tarats ehT
?eitsirhC ,yas uoy od tahW
.ytniatrec erom elttil a htiw evom ot elba saw ordnaeL
.mih raeh ot elba eb t’ndluow yeht taht gnisilaer erofeb
,taorht sih ni thguac htaerb siH .devom yehT
.roiretni elbatrofmocnu eht tsniaga kcab gnidlof
.tuh eht dna knat eht neewteb yaw flah tuoba derutpur yletelpmoc tsomla dah epip ehT
deniatnoc t’nsaw kael eht fI
,tfihs yreve fo dne eht tA
.talf dna llud saw eciov siH .dias ordnaeL
.saw ti esuaceb saw taht wenk ordnaeL neht tub ,edurc dekool tI
.tuo dnats mih edam ruf kcalb dna yerg tcnitsid s’ordnaeL
,ordnaeL ,emit tsaL
,derots erew ria dna retaw rieht lla erehw
.enim ot detcepxe dna erehwon fo elddim eht ni dioretsa na no detisoped erew eitsirhC dna ,nellE
,eid ot gniog eh saw ylno toN
.taht detcepxe dah eh tub
.hcaer fo tuo ylkciuq
.gniyas saw ehs tahw raeh t’ndluoc eh tub
.seye sih morf yleerf gnillaf sraet ,dias ordnaeL
negyxo erom neve gnisol ksir ot evah dluow yeht esle ro
.starats eerht eht rof erutcurts dna enituor fo eno otni denrut ylkciuq efi L
.starats eht fo tnorf ni doots yltnelis erugif ehT
.won ti htiw ecitcarp fo shtnom owt dah ordnaeL tub ,pleh yna tuohtiw no tup ot drawkwa saw tius ehT
.noitar dluoc yeht gnihtemos t’nsaw negyxO
.derettam taht lla saw taht neht
.sreniatnoc egarots eht dna
,ti did yeht woh derednow ordnaeL
.tarats driht eht htiw tuo kcab daeh dna negyxo rieht hsinelper dluow rehto eht elihw
.mih dniheb tuo thgiarts kcuts liat sih dna
.dnuora denrut eh sa delbmert sdnah siH
.mih dniheb nellE otni kcab llef ylwols eh dna
.epat revlis emos rof tik loot eht ni dnuora degammur eh erofeb
,xoF revliS eht m’I
.yrd seye sih depiw dna
.krow rieht fo noititeper decrof eht morf enasni gniog morf sevlesmeht pots ot dah yeht lla saw tI
.hguone yb ton tub
,yaw taht negyxo ssel deen dluow yehT
.seot reh no denrut ehs sa demialcxe eitsirhC ”!tihs yloH“
,ruovaedne sselesu a saw ti wenk eH
]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[   .esnesnon gnitirw lanoisacco rof
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.etal elttil a pu dekcip eb yeht dluohs yaweel syad owt rof hguone evah dluow yeht tnaem taht etar a ta dehsinimid yeht tub
.wolb gnicnalg a ni gnihtemos yb kcurts neeb dah ti ekil dekool tI
.tsum I fi ,flesym reetnulov ll’I“
.em s’eH ?mih teeM“
”,wonk tey ton od I“ .deilper nellE
.deksa namuh eht ”?uoy snwo ohW“
”,eucser rof tiaw ew dna
.seveels gnilaes rebbur ralucric llams fo elpuoc a dnuof eh neht tub
pu deird ria fo duolc gnikael ehT
.ot dedeen fi kcab eitsirhC hsup ot deraperp ,kcolria eht fo tnorf ni doots eH
.eb ot ton saw ti tub
”.kcab uoy deen I fi uoy llac lliw I
.ezis emas eht tuoba dekool yehT
.esle lla evoba ssenippah dna erusaelp no sucof ot emit saw ti daetsnI
starats eerht ehT
.snoititeper sseltnuoc rof ,revo dna revO
.retfa saw ordnaeL tahw t’nsaw taht tub
.won etarip a saw eH
.sgniht doog ylerar erew ecaps ni sesion duol taht esilaer ot hguone wenk eH
,no ti tup dna temleh sih ot revo deirruh tarats ehT
.pmar eht ot derutseg xoF revliS ehT
”.retteb eht pihs ruoy draob no teg ew renoos eht os ,wol si negyxo ruO
”,ylrae pu su kcip emoc ot evah ll’yehT
.desaec ylneddus ecnatsiser eht sa drawrof llef ordnaeL
.no tius sih gnittup nehw deirruh dah eH
,dias eh ”,uoy knahT“
.loS no llits erew seye reh tub
.rehto hcae tsniaga pu depmub stemleh riehT
.werc ruoy nioj ot erusaelp ruo eb lliw ti
.ekirts etanutrofnu eno ni
.pils ot detrats sregnif siH
,doof fo sevreser rieht dekcehc ordnaeL
.seirrow sih tegrof ot elba saw eh tnemom feirb a rof dna
.derehtet ylluf saw ordnaeL erus gnikam
.denworf dna rae sih dekcilf eH
,deldniwd seilppus rieht ylwolS
.ediw sdnah sih gnidaerps ,dias ordnaeL ”...lleW“
.yllufnruom deilper ordnaeL ”,tluaf ym si tI“
.emac reve gnihton tub
.no kcab evlav eht denrut ordnaeL
,ria fo tuo nur noos dluow yehT
kcals dellup sepor rehtet eht nehT
,dias eh ”,yas ot gniog erew uoy thguoht I tahw ton si tahT“
.edivorp dluoc ehs sa tnemevom fo modeerf hcum sa tarats rehto eht gnivig
sruoh evif yrevE
.ni denioj ordnaeL tub
stnemom gnippots traeh fo elpuoc a rof dna
”.yaw rehtona si erehT“
.sselhtrow saw ecifircas A
,meht deniarts eh sa
.sredluohs sih ssorca mra reh detser ehS
.spets rieht ni tnedifnoc demees yeht tub
eb ot hguone dedivorp dah dna ,etaredisnoc neeb dah srenwo namuh riehT
.edisni kcab tog eh retfa tius sih gnivomer rehtob neve t’ndid ordnaeL
.tsehc sih ni esor yteixna fo rettulf A .dias ordnaeL
”.tluaf ruoy ton s’tI“
.mret trohs ehtaerb ot hguone dah yeht erus ekam ot tsuj
.detcennocer erew sevlah owt eht ecno laes retteb a ti ekam dluoc eh tnedifnoc saw ordnaeL tub
,gnipacse saw ria erom oN
.ereht ni sloot emos erew ereht gniwonk ,olis eht ot kcab decar dna denrut eH
.ordnaeL dnuora rethgit dezeeuqs smra s’nellE
.llits dnats t’ndluoc ordnaeL
negyxo dna ,retaw
.rae s’ordnaeL dehcaer eciov a ylnedduS
tuh eht neewteb nar taht sepip eht fo eno morf gnikael duolc llams a saw
.deb eht no ecalp lausu reh morf ,dias eitsirhC
,ti gniraew htiw pu tup ot gnivah tuohtiw sruoh evif rof gnipoh neeb dah eH
”.htaed ot ekohc ew litnu gniggid dna gnikrow peek ot su tcepxe tsuj ll’yehT
”!yks eht ni thgil A !thgil a s’erehT“
,ti nrut ot elba saw eh ylwolS
,thgieh eht morf gnigduJ
,meht neewteb knil eht detset ehS .deilper nellE
.no ti tup ot dah eh emit yreve eson sih elknirw ot dah eh tub
.ffo ti gniwohs deyojne dna
,ereht hcum t’nsaw erehT
.won noziroh eht dniheb morf gnigreme saw loS
.tsael ta tey ton ,oN“
.epat revlis evitcelfer eht ni detaoc yletelpmoc saw eveels kcalb eritne eht erofeb htiw yawa teg dluoc eh sa sreyal ynam sa gnidda
setaocrfj@ ta rettiwT no mih wollof nac uoY
,pihs eht nihtiw morf degreme snamuh erom eerhT
.syad erom neves-ytnewt rof ereh er’eW“
dehgual ordnaeL ”.niaga esirnus eht
.elbatrofmoc ylbanosaer
,deralf ylfeirb skraps wef A
,ylluf epip eht hguorht ecils ot rewop eht evah dluow yehT
”?od dluohs ew tahw wonk uoY“
.llew sa ti erimda ot yppah neeb dah snoinapmoc owt sih
?puorg gniniM ?yeh ,nosretsaM“
.renroc eno ni yawa dekcut srosnes eht ot ssorca yaw sih edam dna
.mih raeh t’ndluoc owt rehto eht taht rettam neve t’ndid tI
lufknaht eb ylno dluoc ordnaeL
,ti hsaw ot retaw suoicerp rieht fo yna etsaw ot tnaw t’ndid ordnaeL
.slevel negyxo gnitelped eht erongi ot tseb rieht deirt starats eerht eht skeew eerht roF
.ria fo tuo gninnur fo daerd eht ot derapmoc gnihton saw niap elttil A
.enips sih nwod nar revihs dloc A
,yad yreve sevreser rieht dekcehc ordnaeL
.dioretsa eht morf derevocer saw ti nehw no gnidneped dekcats saw ti fo tsom tub
.hguone neeb t’ndah ti tub
.rethgual ni gnikahs sredluohs reh ees dluoc ordnaeL tub ,dias ehs gnihtyna tsacdaorb t’ndid nellE
”?kcab emoc ot su tnaw uoy oD
.dah eh sloot eht ot nwod decnalg tarats ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”,edisni kcehc ot deen I .tey taht wonk ton od I“
,noitalosi rieht ni ytuaeb dnuof yehT
temleh sih deppilcnu ylpmis eH
,latem dna kcor fo elip gnirewot a saw tI
.kael eht fo tnorf ni dnats ot mih wolla ot hguone raf og t’ndid ylpmis epor rehtet ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,setaoC .R.F.J yb
.skcap negyxo eraps rieht gnillifer ron
.ecaps fo muucav eht otni yawa detsalb kcor fo sknuhc egral htiw
.wolf ria eht dellortnoc taht evlav eht dnuora sregnif sih teg dna tuo smra sih hcterts ot elba tuoba tsuj saw ordnaeL
,edistuo skcart rehtet eht ot flesmih deknil eh retfA
”?tuoba kniht reve uoy lla taht sI .elam ytrid uoY“
.mih dniheb starats owt eht sdrawot
.neeb evah t’ndluohs uoy ,oN“
.deilper eitsirhC
ees oG“
2 fo 2 traP ,setaoC .R.F.J yb
rewot eht fo esab eht ta srood llams fo elpuoc a nepo dehcnerw eh daetsnI
.tarats rehto eht ot ssorca deppans seye s’ordnaeL
,nwod gnihcuorc ylluferaC
.sih tsniaga ruf reh fo tcatnoc esolc eht deyojne eh dna
.gninim tfihs elbuod sih dehsinif tsuj dah ordnaeL
.redluohs eht ssorca ylthgil ordnaeL deppals dna delkcac ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,kaew tlef sgel siH
,truh sredluohs siH
.hcum oot kcab mih hsup t’ndid detrexe yeht ecrof eht luferac eb ot evah dluow eh tub
nwod emac ylwols ti erofeb ,dioretsa eht evoba derevoh tsuj pihs eht ,setunim wef a roF
”?t’nac ew ylneddus litnu gnihtaerb peek tsuj eW“
.tey ti hguorht ton era ew tub ,uoy knahT“
.deraelc rosiv detnit s’namuh ehT
.tnedifnoc dna ydaets eciov sih peek ot deirt eH .dias ordnaeL
.muucav eht otni desrepsid dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.hcnerw neddus a htiw yaw evag yllanif ti erofeb
,gnidliub eritne eht koohs tI
,ylthgils dneb ti gnileef ,epip eht no detsiwt dna dellup eH
.retlehs rieht fo edis eht dnuora dehcni ylluferac ordnaeL
.eveels rebbur eht htaeneb rehtegot epip eht fo strap owt eht llup ot elba saw ordnaeL tub
.dnuorg eht evoba hgih deraos ydaerla evah dluow eh
,etsaw htiw laed dna esiminim pleh ot ti nihtiw smetsys eht etipseD
.emoc t’ndid yehT *** ”.emoc lliw yehT“
.llems ot gnitrats saw tius eht ,taews gnidulcni
,dleh dah sepip eht no sriaper siH
.enog dah yrrow rof emit ehT
htaerb reh htaeneb yltfos delworg ehS
.ruf s’ordnaeL morf deppird taewS
lla ta evom t’ndluoc ordnaeL sdnoces wef a roF
”,owt gniniamer eht rof ria hguone s’ereht neht tuB“
.tuo dehtaerb ylwols eitsirhC ”?yaw rehto tahW“
,enif llits erew slevel retaW
”?mih teem ot teg ew od nehW“
,deb eht ffo gnitaolf ton elihw peels ot gniyrt tneps saw tuh llams eht ni tseR
.taeper dna eunitnoc dluow elcyc eht os dnA
,dednarb ton saw pihs ehT
.nellE htiw skool krad emos erahs yllanoisacco did eitsirhC hguoht
”.werc sih nioj ot emoclew era eerht uoy dna
.roop saw langis eht os
.rehtet sih deppilcnu eh sa koohs sdnah siH
”.ti gnilaes pleh deen yam I .nac uoy sa kciuq sa kcab emoC
,ruf sih fo duorp neeb syawla dah eH
,deworc ordnaeL ”,ereht ,oN“
.rehtruf deppils sregnif siH
,rehto hcae decarbme starats eerht eht ,ria eht otni smra rieht gnivaw fo daetsnI
elkcub ot detrats ylwols
”,laed a ekil sdnuoS“
.smra rieht ni pu sevlesmeht gnipparw
,ylreporp no ti tog d’eh setunim net nihtiW
.tuh llams rieht edisni rehtegot tneserp erew yeht nehw snoisacco wef erew ereht dna ,ytidun s’rehto hcae dednim starats eht fo enon tub
.ecafrus ykcor eht tih ot deliaf teef htob
.taorht reh deraelc eitsirhC
.edis sih yb tis ot pu delffuhs eitsirhC dna
,rehtruf yna olis eht gnillif ni tniop on saw erehT
”.etagitsevni dna niaga pu tius lliw I
,ees ot yppah saw ordnaeL thgis a yllausu saw ruf maerc dna eeffoc reH
.daeherof sih revo elbisiv riah fo kcol revlis a htiw namuh gnuoy a saw temleh eht edisnI
,ecno ta dnopser ot deirt starats htoB
.tsol neeb ydaerla dah taht negyxo eht rof enod eb dluoc taht gnihton saw ereht tub
.gniniamer noitpo eno tsuj tfel tahT
,xoF revliS rM“
.kcals dellup epor rehtet eht sa
.srenwo rieht morf t’nsaw ti taht wenk ordnaeL os
.gel thgir sih htiw nwod deffuts yldrawkwa ti htiw neve
.temleh rieht ot dnah rieht dleh regnarts suoiretsym ehT
ecarbme s’nellE fo tuo devom eH
,elbissop sa desinagro sa lla ti peek ot gniyrt neeb dah starats eerht ehT
.gniliec eht ta pu derats ehs dna
”,htrow shtnom eerhT“
.ssenkrad eht otni pu gnikool
.olis eht dehcaorppa lla yeht dna
.stnemecalper on ylniatrec dna
.pu kool neve t’ndid eh emit siht tub
.temleh sih fo edis eht tsniaga dnah sih gnippat ylno
*** .od ot elba ylisae saw ordnaeL gnihtemos saw tI
.deb eht revo ti epard ot tius sih fo tuo delggurts dah eh dna
.tnemom a rof deretlaf ylno elzzum reh ssorca elims ediw ehT .dias eitsirhC
.slareniM noretsaM htiw edutivres ruoy morf uoy eerf ybereh I“
.sniev sih hguorht desruoc rorreT
,epip nekorb eht hcaer t’ndluoc eh ,saw melborp ehT
.egamad eht deciton eh taht
,elttil a dehctiwt rae sih
”ykS ehT nI sthgiL“
.hcum oot sevlesmeht trexe t’ndid yeht os
,yldrawkwa dehcnip saw liat siH
.oot eitsirhC dna nellE llik dluow eh tub
.emit tsal eht rof retlehs llams rieht edistuo doots starats eerht ehT
,tuh rieht ni gnitalucric ria yna saw ron tub
.meht eucser ot gnimoc saw ti ,ylbissopmI
,noitautis erid rieht etipseD
.tuh elttil eht edisni sruoh wef tsal rieht ot kcab og dluow yeht neht
nocaeb ssertsid eht etavitca I“
”.og ot eno eht neeb evah dluohs I
,kcab eht ot dnuora tog eh litnu t’nsaw tI
.dloc tnew doolb s’ordnaeL
,edalb gninnips eht fo ecrof eht rednu dneb dna
,mih detatirri tI
.meht tcelloc ot emoc srenwo rieht ees reven dluow yeht nevig
.ero dna slarenim dessecorpnu fo lluf saw olis ehT
.namuh eht sdrawot tuo dnah devolg sih dleh dna drawrof deppets ordnaeL
,duht gnirraj a htiw dnuorg eht tih eH
”.yaw rehto yna t’nsi erehT“
starats eerht ehT
”.gniniamer ria fo syad eerht-ytnewt evah eW
dehgual starats eht
.emit emas eht ta tik loot eht gnippord
,ti fo ssel saw erehT
,derehtet erew meht fo enoN
.ria eht ni pu smra reh werht ehS
,namuh tseraen eht yb nekat noos saw noitnetta sih tub
.erutpur eht fo edis rehtie
.tnorf sih otno revo dellor eh sa derettum eh
.sgnidaer negyxo eht was eh nehw yrd tnew taorht siH
.dewollof esuap feirb A
.ot no dloh ot tfel hcum t’nsaw erehT
.yawa ti epiw ot od dluoc eh gnihton saw ereht tub
,ylkciuq deilper ordnaeL ”,uoy raeh I“
epip ehT .gniwolf negyxo erom on saw ereht lufknaht saw eh dna
.temleh s’ordnaeL edisni srekaeps eht ssorca derevaw eciov reH .deksa eitsirhC
.dnuora denrut dna desuap eh
semit wef a delbmuts eH
htaerb peed a koot ordnaeL
.ylsuovren dehctiwt liat sih fo pit ehT .dias ordnaeL
,namuh eht morf kcab pets a flah koot eH .dias ordnaeL
.oot erew sreh dnif ot desirprus saw eh dna ,tiaw erew skeehc siH
.taht sa elpmis sa saw ti
,sepip eht tsniaga decnuob eH
.sepip eht ot pu eveels rebbur eht pu dleh ordnaeL
.woble sih dnuora deppirg dnah A
.mih fo pot no derebmalc starats elamef owt eht sa deb eht ot nwod dennip flesmih dnuof ordnaeL
.meht ecaf ot kcab denrut dah ohw
.namuh erew yeht llet dluoc ordnaeL
.gniliec eht ffo roolf eht ot kcab flesmih hsup ot dah dna ylkciuq oot teef sih ot esor eH .dekrab ordnaeL
.kcolria eht sdrawot dekcilf seye reH
sdnah sih morf llef edalb gnittuc eht dna
epor rehtet sih pu kcip ot nwod dehcuorc eH
.nocaeb ssertsid eht reggirt ll’I“
,hcum oot tsol yeht fI
.sedalb gnittuc eht deraperp ordnaeL
.sruoh eerht yreve gnineppah etipsed
pu deffup dah ruf siH
”,slareniM nosretsaM“
”.erew ti sa ,gnab a htiw tuo gnioG
,dioretsa eht fo edis raf eht no gninim erew yeht taht wenk ordnaeL tub ,tcnitsidni dna ylkcarc saw tI
.don a htiw dias ordnaeL ”,rehtegot eb ll’ew ,haeY“
gnihtyreve tsomlA
”.noos uoy morf raeH
.niaga nwod kcab mih deggard dna
.dnim nwo sih fo esae rof tsuj saw ti yltsom tub ,nwod mih dloh ot ytivarg neeb ereht dah dekrow evah dluow tI
.tibro fo tuo flesmih tloj t’ndid eh os ylwols os evom ot gniyrt
.esirnus erofeb llits sruoh fo elpuoc a tog ev’ew kniht I hguohT“
”?ereht thgirla gnihtyreve sI
.dnim ni namuh a fo smra regnol eht htiw dengised neeb dah metsys ehT
.teef sih no saw ordnaeL yletaidemmi dna
.desaec negyxo fo wolf eht dna
”,uoy fo dloh a peek ll’eW“
,eucser rieht dlareh ot yks eht ni sthgil rof depoh eH
.reh ees ot elba eb dluow pihs tnatsid eht hguoht sa ria eht ni smra reh gnivaw
,elzzum sih no elims a htiW
.rae sih ni citats fo ssem delbrag a tsuj gnivael
.gnol rof tius eht gniraew eb t’ndluow eH
”.siht xif ot evah llits I .derehtet em peeK
.dluoc eh tseb sa segde delknirc eht nwod htooms ot deirt eh erofeb
.ecalp suoregnad a si ecaps tub
.ylmrif flesmih dnuorg dna yrt ot ediw sgel sih tpek eH
,neewteb semit tser regral htiw stfihs rellams dekrow dah yehT
.ekam dluoc eh eciohc eno ylno saw erehT
.tuo gid dluoc yeht taht slarenim eht lla gnirehtag dna ecafrus ykcor eht otni gnillird tneps saw krow dna
.won enilefil ylno sih
,nellE ot kcab llor eht fo redniamer eht dednah eH
.kcab dellup neeb dah eh yhw esilaer eh did neht ylnO
.temleh sih no nottub rotacinummoc eht tsniaga deppals rehto sih dna
.gnineppah ton s’tahT“
.flesmih ydaets ot sdnah htob ni sepip eht fo dloh deppirg ordnaeL
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dedaelp ordnaeL ”,ti yrt ot evah eW .emoc thgim yehT“
.ecalp ni yleruces temleh eht gnippilc saw dna
,niaga sevlesmeht ecifircas ot reffo eht pu thguorb reve eno on
.noziroh etisoppo eht fo thgis thguac ordnaeL
”.esirnus eht nees ev’ew retfa t’nac ew yhw nosaer on si erehT“
”.evivrus htob uoy snaem ti fI
,ssensuovren ni dehctiwt llits liat siH
.seye rieht teem t’ndid dna dewob daeh sih tpek eH
.flesmih ot decamirg ordnaeL
.ot no dloh ot esle gnihtemos dnif ot deirt eh sa
.enituor rieht saw taht shtnom owt roF
.dniheb lla ti tfel eh sa delims tarats ehT
nellE .mih dah ehS
,tiag sih ni pmil hserf a htiW
.detroter nellE ”,taht od t’now yeht wonk uoY“
.epip eht morf sregnif sih dekoohnu eh sa temleh sih edisni yltfos derepmihw eH
.olis eht sdrawot dekool namuh ehT
.tsehc sih ot esolc degguh
.evah reve dluoc starats eht lla saw taht dna
,dniheb niamer dluow tarats enO
tnempiuqe suoicerp sih htiw tuh llams eht ot kcab decar ordnaeL
pihs sih ot kcab denrut namuh ehT
,hguoht rednow rieht tsol ecno reven sesirnus ehT
.no gnihsup tpek ordnaeL
,deilper nellE ”,ti ees I ,haeY“
.deb tseraen eht otno nwod deppord nellE
.pihs eht fo edis raen eht morf nwod derewol pmar a sa tsuj
.guh drawkwa na otni htob meht dellup eh dna
,epip eht no pirg nori sih rof tuB
.pu detaolf dna epip eht revo deppilf tarats ehT
,sepor rehtet reh ot pu ordnaeL dekooh ylkciuq
.redluohs sih no detser dnah A
,tik nepo eht hguorht dehcraes ordnaeL
.gnitniop saw eh erehw ees dluoc ehs os dnuora nellE gnillup
”ykS ehT nI sthgiL“   :yojne esaelP
.noziroh eht sdrawot derats yeht dnah ni dnaH
.evals a regnol on saw eH
.deksa eciov elam a ”?ycneuqerf sihT“
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht eht saw sihT
”.eripme eht fo egruocs dna etarip demaf
.su tuoba tihs a evig t’nod yehT“
.ereht srats eht tuoba egnarts demees gnihtemoS
”?slarenim fo stol toG
”,lliw lla ew daetsnI“
,hguoht raf teg t’ndid eH
tsuj edistuo setunim net tneps ordnaeL
.delaeuqs nellE ”,taerg s’taht hO“
.retal stnemom wef a kcab emac esnopser A ”.esaelp ni kcehC“
.deknilb namuh ehT
,epip eht no pirg sih tpek eh sa deniarts mra siH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.saw meht xiffa ot yaw tseb eht tahw derednow dna elzzum sih dehctiwt eH
,laes rebbur eht dnuora epat eht depparw tarats ehT
”?tneve gib eht fo retsat elttil a tnaW
”,ton yletulosba ,oN“
niap ni mih ta demaercs redluohs dna woble siH
.kcolria eht otni tuo deppets dna
.yletaidemmi ffo dehctiws dna
,tser fo sruoh evif yb dewollof saw krow fo sruoh neT
,resolc yna teg t’ndluoc eh hguohT
,ylkciuq kael eht xif ot dah eH
.starats eht fo rehtie ot kaeps t’ndid ordnaeL
.deb sih ssorca depard dah eh taht tius eht ta nwod dekool eH
,tif tcefrep a t’nsaw tI
,erom ecno dnuorg eht no nwod dehcuot teef sih sa delbmert ydob elohw siH
.won taht rof gniyap erew starats ehT
,spets suovren fo elpuoc a gnikaT
.deb reh fo dne eht tsniaga tius reh depard dah ehS .deksa nellE
.ecaps otni tuo gnikael ria suoicerp rieht dehctaw eh sa
,dnah ta noitautis eht ot sselesu ylrettu saw
.delworg ordnaeL ”,sevlesmeht ecifircas ot gniog si eno oN