.traeh sih fo gniremmah eht leef dluoc eH
,ssorca sertemolik wef a ylno ,llams saw tI
,stesdaeh owt rehto eht htiw etacinummoc ot srekaeps eht detavitca hcihw
,nigeb ot saw od ot tfel saw taht llA
,lufrewop dna thgirb saw thgil eht
.sserttam eht ffo ylthgils decnuob dna ylwols nwod detfird tsuj ehs ,daetsnI
,dellatsni neeb dah ti nehw eguh dekool dah olis ehT
”?yeht did ,starats rof stius eseht ekam ton did yeht ,wO“
”.won thgir taht uoy llet nac I ,dilos shtnom eerht rof ti gniraew ton ma I“
”.erup dna tneconni era taht srednow gniees
.rae depmarc nwo sih yb ylno draeh eciov sih
,krow lufsserts saw tI
,sruoh wef a revO
.retarc eht fo ecafrus eht no sehsimelb dna sretarc eht hguorht decreip thgil fo syaR
.slairetam tseb eht starats evig t’ndluow snamuh ehT
.doof su evig ot derebmemer yeht tsael tA“
.teef reh ot esor ylluferac ehS
”ykS ehT nI sthgiL“   :yojne esaelP
,noos dluow taht olis evissam eht ni nwod tis lla meht dah ordnaeL ,os did yeht erofeb tub
.sdioretsa tsom ot tnereffid on saw 3AR7552 .nwod srosiv rieht tuohtiw ti sdrawot dekool ohw esoht fo seye eht nrub tub elttil did ,loS
,kcor eht otni nwod sgep eht deremmah ordnaeL emit yreve sa
.deilper eitsirhC
daeh sih koohs tarats derruf-yerg ehT
”?riaf dnuos taht seoD .gninim owt dna
,neddih saw loS nehw nevE
.doof detardyhed fo stekcap fo elpuoc a tuo dleh tarats ehT
.dias elddim eht ni tarats eht
,shtnom eerht lluf eht rof negyxo evah eW .ereh retaw dna doof si erehT
”.efil taht evah ot ,hO“
.klat ot temleh sih fo edis eht ot dnah sih dloh ot dah eH .dias ordnaeL
elbixelf a fo reyal kciht a yb erutcurts eht fo esab eht ta deniatniam saw laes thgitria nA
.temleh sih no rekaeps eht ni desserp eh dna ,mih dniheb deppots yehT
.ecafrus s’kcor eht ot deruces meht peek dluow taht srehtet eht nwod yal ot saw ksat tnatropmi tsom ehT
noziroh eht no tniop tsethgirb eht sdrawot detniop eH .deilper ordnaeL
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,slaem rieht dehsinif dah yeht ecnO
sdrow eciohc wef a derettum ordnaeL
.nees reve evah I gniht lufituaeb tsom ehT .si yllaer tI“
.lataf eb dluoc nwod srehtet eht tog yeht erofeb petssim enO
”,taht llif ot tnaw ew fi kcor siht tuo wolloh ot evah ot gniog er’eW“
.erutcurts citnagig eht fo edis eht tsniaga dnah reh deppals ehS .dias nellE
.moor ynit eht fo edistuo evila mih peek dluow taht gniht ylno eht saw ti sa edisa ti ssot ot tnaw t’ndid eh
ordnaeL ”,depmarc yllufwa si liat yM“
ti dehcaorppa starats eerht eht sa tub
2 fo 1 traP ,setaoC .R.F.J yb
”.edisni teg dluohs eW“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht eht saw sihT
.erofeb ralimis ffo devivrus dah ordnaeL tub
”.elihw a rof krow ot enif eb lliw I os ,pihs eht no detser I
.snoinapmoc sih ecaf ot denrut oirt eht fo thgir eht no tarats ehT
.tnemnorivne gnihtaerb efas a ni saw eh taht noitacifiton a degnip temleh sih moor llams eht edisni deppets ordnaeL nehw tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sepor dna srehtet eht dnuof eH
,dab etsat t’nod yehT .esrow eb dluoC“
.dekcilf srae siH
dah yeht litnu od ot rehto hcae ot edam dah yeht esimorp a
.dias eh ”,sevlesmeht yb ereht tuo gnikrow eno on tnaw I“
thgil fo kcirpnip
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.lacitnedi dekool eno elgnis yrevE
.moor eht fo dne raf eht ta rehtegot deldnub erew seilppus rehtO
.tnelis dna llits saw llA
.semit fo tseb eht ta elbatrofmocnu saw tI
,llew sa temleh reh devomer dah tarats rehto ehT
,retipuJ dna sraM neewteb yawflah tuoba
”?tser tsrif steg ohW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.meht ot elbaliava dah yeht smetsys wef eht nur ot deen d’yeht rewop eht htiw meht gnidivorp
,olis eht edisni derehtet nevE
sih htiw cigam dna snogard fo rohtua eht ,setaoC .R.F.J yb
.sdeb eht fo tsesolc eht no nwod temleh sih decalp yltneg eH .deilper
.ecafrus eht ffo pu mih hsup ot gninetaerht mutnemom eht leef dluoc eh
nosretsaM‘ .tfarc eht fo edis eht no denozalbme erew srettel der giB
.yleritne pihs eht fo thgis tsol dah yeht litnu
.llaw eno denil sdeb eerhT
elzzum sih fo ruf kcalb dna yerg eht revo dnah devolg a dehsurb ordnaeL
.doof etanimretedni fo rab sselruovalf reh fo lufhtuom rehtona nwod dewollaws ehS .deksa nellE
”,dekan gnitteg tuoba gniklat ydaerla er’uoy dna ,shtnom eerht rof flesruoy yb seidal ylevol owt dnuorA .elam lacipyT“
.mra reh htaeneb yleruces ti gnidloh
,rood eht nepo dellup ordnaeL
”,oot ruovalf emas eht lla eb thgim yeht kniht I
.nellE saw hcihw dna
”ykS ehT nI sthgiL“
.ecaf reh evoba pu rab eht fo tser eht dleh ehS
.elacs reehs sti fo esnes a tog ylurt yeht
,esab ta tarats eno syawla s’ereht os etator nac eW
kcor fo knuhc llams hcaE
.dellatsni saw tnempiuqe eht
,meht morf deklaw eh yawa raf woh rettam oN
.retteb gnihtyna fo kniht t’nac I“
.meht dnuora nwod enohs yltnatsnoc thgilrats eht fo maelg eht sa
.olis eht ni lla saw tnempiuqe gninim eht
.sepor gnidiug eht ot dna
.noziroh eht dnoyeb morf egreme ot detrats ylwols loS sa
,tuo eugnot reh kcuts dna elzzum reh dehctiwt ehS
.eciov s’eitsirhC desingocer ordnaeL
”,ti rof shtnom eerht evah eW“
.tcapmi eht raeh yllautca t’ndluoc eh taht eiree saw ti tub
”,tnaillirb s’taht hO“ .emit emas eht ta rab eht otni tib ylevitatnet dna laem tsrif rieht depparwnu starats eerht eht ,rehtegoT
,gniht eht detah eh sa hcum sA
,em tsurT .tnit lluF“
demaelg serutcurts htoB
.hgual a htiw deilper ordnaeL
.ruf sih pu nesool ot
”,syad fo elpuoc a tsuj retfa devrats werc eht dna ,pu tes noitats gninim eno saw ereht draeh I
”?ylecin ksa I fi ereh tcartnoc ym dnetxe ll’yeht knihT“
”.ereh thgir deen ew lla evah ew tub
srenim eht rof retlehs eht eb dluow taht
.shtnom eerht txen eht rof aera krow rieht eraperp ot detrats starats eerht eht
,olis eht fo pot tnatsid eht sdrawot pu dekool yeht sa denarc skcen rieht
kcor eht otni dellird yeht litnu t’nsaw tI
.elbatrofmoc ylniatrec saw ti tarats a rof os
.srekaeps temleh rieht hguorht ylraelc mih raeh dluow yeht wenk eh
.werc tarats elpmis a rof deraps eb t’ndluow taht nwonk syawla dah eh tub
.emit a ta negyxo fo sruoh xis dloh nac stius ruo sa
ecafrus eht ssorca klaw dluoc starats eerht eht ,tuo dial
rettiwT no mih wollof nac uoY
.pu gnikrep srae reh ,dias nellE
.ria eht hguorht detaolf ylwols ti sa rab eht thguac llits ehs tub
yks kcalb sseldne na tub gnihton saw ereht yllausU
.rosiv sih denekrad eh sa
,wols erew srood ehT
.noitadommocca rieht ot dnuora devom ylwols yeht erofeb
.deilper ordnaeL ”,tser tsrif evah nac uoY“
.deb eht otno nwod flesreh worht ot deirt ehs sa deredduhs ehS .dias nellE
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,setaoC .R.F.J yb
.llaw etisoppo eht denil slaem detardyhed fo skcatS
neeb dah rae gniniamer enol siH
.emit emas eht ta ereht tuo su fo lla tnaw I od ron tuB“
,tnemom feirb a roF
.starats rehto owt eht ta dekool eh sa
.thgiled ni deworc nellE
.temleh sih fo edis eht no nottub eht rof delbmuf eh sa koohs dnah siH
.tneced ...era snoitidnoc ,ereh era eW
.tleb eht ni eton fo esle gnihtyna
.tunaep a ekil ylhguor depahs dna
eitsirhC saw owt eht fo hcihw llet t’ndluoc ordnaeL dna
”,siht ees ot tnaw ll’uoy
.sredluohs reh deggurhs dna rab eht ta deffins ehS .deksa eitsirhC
,reilrae shtnom deyevrus neeb dah dioretsa eritne ehT
,smra deknilretni rieht hguorht snoitarbiv eht leef dluoc ordnaeL
.ecafrus sti no tfarc gnidnal a dah osla tI
.dioretsa eht fo ecafrus eht ssorca yaw sih edam ylluferac eh sa
,slarenim eht rof llird yllautca ot gnihton saw erehT
,nwod mih gnidloh nellE dna eitsirhC rof t’nsaw ti fI
.emit gnol yrev a rof evah d’yeht tcatnoc tsal eht eb dluow ti wenk
.yltnatsnoc hcum ytterp gnikrow eb ot deen ll’ew os
.meht dednuorrus taht muucav eht ot tsol eb dluow edam yeht dnuos yna esle ro
”,skrow ylerab taht parc detsur s’ti taht laem eno uoy teB“
rehtona ot hguone esolc kcor a saw ylerar yrev ylnO
.edis eno ot gnorts ylralucitrap saw wolg ehT
.ecaps ytpme otni gnitaolf morf yawa pirt eno erew yeht ekil gnileef yltnatsnoc tuohtiw
”,lufthgiled sdnuoS“
*** ”.em no worg ot gnitrats yllaer si siht kniht I ,wonk uoY“
.artxe syad fo elpuoc suoreneg a neve dna
.kcor ylenol rieht no ecnediser gnikat eb dluow taht
.tius ecaps eht hguorht retsum dluoc eh sa ecrof hcum sa htiw ti otno gnippirg
spih sih no sdnah sih decalp ordnaeL
.llaw eno gnola pu delip erew taht srab fo skcats eht revo dnah devolg sih nar eH
,tsrif tuh gnisuoh dna olis eht ot deruces erew sepor kciht ehT
.srats tnatsid eht ot pu dekool eH
.kcor llams eht ot eruces erom meht peek dluow taht senil rehtet eht ni deremmah
.hcum oot ecafrus eht ffo taolf sevlesmeht leef ot detnaw ylralucitrap starats eht fo enon
.srats fo sdnasuoht htiw dellif
.eitsirhC ,nac uoy nehT“
dekool gnihtyrevE
.ni emoc ot txen saw nellE
.slairetam suoicerp rehto dna sero hcir htiw dellif eb ,yllufepoh
.rehto hcae morf elbisiv erew yeht taht
,derehtet erew syawhtap ehT
.dioretsa eht fo ecafrus ykcor eht otni nwod deremmah erew yeht erofeb
.lufwa era sgniht esehT .uoy teg I
.dias nellE ”,krad llits s’tI“
”.skcen ruo revo gnihtaerb snamuh on evah ew ,tey tseb dnA“
nottub a saw erehT
tuh llams a saw edis sti oT
”ykS ehT nI sthgiL“
ynit a tsuj saw ti erofeb gnol t’nsaw tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.snoziroh esolc eht dnuora wolg llams a syawla saw ereht
,detcepxe dah ordnaeL sA
,ti ni pu doots evah dluoc namuh a hguone llat saw tuh llams ehT
.nwod kcab mih deggut yltneg nellE
revo fo sdnasuoht fo dleif a tsgnoma
”.tnit lluf no srosiV“
,kcalb hctip tsomla tnew gnihtyrevE
,loS detibro ti sa ylkciuq nups dioretsa ehT
.elzzum sih ssorca ekorb elims eniuneg A
.dioretsa eht ssorca shtap efas etaerc ot hguone saw ereht taht epoh ylno dluoc eh dna
.elbirret etsat yllausu t’ndid ti dnuof netfo dah eH
”,su nevig evah yeht syot tahw ees ew llahS
yks krad eht otni pu derats yehT
,redluohs s’ordnaeL deppals ehS
,tcartxe ot er’ew slarenim hcum woh ni stegrat citsimitpo ytterp emos tes neeb ev’eW
?won laem yrotarbelec a evah ton yhw tub
.sredluohs reh deggurhs nellE
,rats tsesolc eht nevE
,emit a ta eno kcolria eht hguorht og ylno dluoc yehT
.snamuh trohs rof dengised stius edisni desserpmoc dna dehcnip tsomla saw taht ruf fo reyal kciht a ni derevoc
.detalosi saw ti ,taht naht erom tuB
.dedivorp spam eht no dethgilhgih neeb lla dah slarenim hcir eht rof snoiger ylekil eht lla dna
,dlo fo srerolpxe eht ekil eb nac eW
.ecalp krad ,dloc a saw tleB dioretsA ehT
stius rieht ot denetsaf yleruces erew skooh eht luferac eb ot dedeen tsuj yeht daetsnI
.nepo meht dehsup eh os
.mra reh rednu temleh reh dleh ehs sa srae reh debbur ehs ,ordnaeL ekiL
,gnicaf saw eh noitcerid tahw ni ro
.ytirgetni sti desimorpmoc ti esac ni tsuj
”.draobdrac eht etsat yllaer nac I“
.ffo tfihs eno ,no stfihs owT
dioretsa eht fo ecafrus eht no dniheb tfel starats eerht ehT
.nosirapmoc ni ynit dekool tI
thgil fo kcirpnip eht rof tub
,hcuot erad t’ndid ordnaeL
stiusecaps ysmulc ,kciht riehT
wolg ot deraeppa dioretsa eritne eht
,temleh sih otni ekops eH .delims ordnaeL
.dioretsa eht morf detraped pihs eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,dnah yb deirrac eb ot dengised lla saw tI
.esu rof ydaer saw gnihtyreve taht tnedifnoc yllanif saw ordnaeL ,noitaraperp fo sruoh lareves retfA
,hsum nworb tcnitsidni fo rab a ekil tsuj dekool doof eht ,srepparw eht nihtiW
ecaps fo ytuaeb eht woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
lluks sih fo pot eht tsniaga nwod dehsurc yltnatsnoc
sepop ecaps dna starats fo dna
.retaw ot detrats yeht sa seye sih treva ot ordnaeL gnicrof
,etelpmoc erew serutcurts eht ecnO
.ti gnivomer yllufetarg erofeb
”?ruovalf a evah yehT“
,elbatrofmoc eb ton yam tI
,teb s’eitsirhC pu koot eno oN
,elbaliava ygolonhcet retteb saw ereht wenk ordnaeL dna ,yratnemidur
.olis eht nihtiw tpek eb dluow yeht taht demussa eh tub
,srood eht ot tsesolc eht saw ordnaeL
”,kcolria na su evag yllautca yeht ,tihs yloH“
,ffo temleh sih htiw ordnaeL gnieeS
.dioretsa eht fo snoiger htooms wef eht fo eno no
.esnopser ni dnuorg eht ffo tfil teef sih tlef tarats eht dna
.kcor eht gnitaoc tsud fo reyal enif eht ffo detcelfer thgilnus eht sa
.taht naht erom yna tif t’ndluow ti sa
”.ruovalf a evah yeht yas t’ndluow tihs sa erus I tuB .esoppus I
.ecaps suonrevac eht dnuora decap ylwols eh sa gnidnats deniamer eH
taht lairetam yrebbur
.raef I ,evah ew lla si tI“
.kcor ynit eht no dehcrep ylsuoiracerp saw pihs thgirb ,keels A
.dioretsa eht fo kcor erab eht saw teef sih htaeneB
.evrats ton lliw ew ,lleW“
erew srehtet eht ecnO .ton ro tcerroc neeb dah syevrus esoht fi wonk d’yeht erofeb
.elzzum reh ssorca ecamirg a htiw snoinapmoc fo puorg llams reh dnuora dekool ehS
.derepsihw eitsirhC ”,lufituaeb s’tI“
,retal ylreporp tuo eseht noitar llahs I“
,foor eht detaoc slenap raloS
.arreT no sreparcsyks emos naht rellat ,citnagig saw tI
”.og ot ti tnaw ton od I secalp otni pu gnidir speeK
morf selim fo sdnasuoht
.gnidloh neeb dah eh htaerb eht tuo tel ylwols ordnaeL ”.yrroS“
.yawa detfird evah dluow ylbaborp eh neht
,seires snogarD fo ynitseD
.seires nrobeR eht ni
.nwo sti no loS detibro ylwols
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,stfihs ruoh evif evah llahs eW
.dias eitsirhC ”,em ot riaf sdnuoS“
.gnillird rof detangised neeb dah taht aera tsrif eht dna ,gnisuoh ,olis eht neewteb tuo dial erew shtap
,rood eht tsniaga sdnah sih decarb ylkciuq eH
,ecalp ni temleh sih tpek taht spsalc eht dnif ot kcen sih fo kcab eht dnuora delbmuf eH
,temleh gnittif-lli eht edisni
,haN“ .gnidnopser ta stpmetta deretsulf s’ordnaeL ta tuo eugnot reh kcuts dna dehgual ehS .dias nellE
.mih tsap gniklaw morf starats owt rehto eht pots ot smra sih tuo tup ordnaeL
.loS morf thgil erup ,thgirb eht ni
.ekil detsat doof tahw tegrof ot flesruoy decrof uoy sa gnol oS
.moor llams eht dnuora dekool eh sa
”.retal krow ot teg nac ew neht dnA
.gnol os rof taht htiw gnilaed ot drawrof gnikool ton saw eh dna
.nihtiw rood reidruts ,dnoces a dnif ot ylno
.sthgil etihw ,llams
.esnesnon gnitirw lanoisacco rof setaocrfj@ ta
.meht dniheb ffo dehctiws olis eht gnitanimulli neeb dah taht thgil mid ehT
;dnah ni dnah deklaw eerht ehT
,dioretsa eht no latot etiuq reven saw ssenkrad ehT
.shtnom eerht rof ereh era ew ,lleW“
.dioretsa eht dnuora setis gninim eht morf dna ot dehsup eb dluoc taht nogaw egral a htiw
.seilppus dedivorp eht fo emos hguorht hcraes ot denrut dna elzzum sih pu delknirw ordnaeL
.ytilauq ralucitrap fo gnihtyna nevig neeb evah dluow yeht detbuod ordnaeL hguoht
,noitces suoiverp eht ot derehtet sevlesmeht
”?neht gniog teg ew llahS“
.regnad latrom ot nrut noos nac
,trapa rehto hcae llet ot drah ti edam
,erutaerc ekil-lesaew a saw eH
,regnol stnemom wef a rof deregnil yehT .deilper ordnaeL
.sreh devomer yletaidemmi ehs
,rosiv detnit ylluf eht hguorht nevE
detcurtsnoc neeb dah olis egral A
.’slareniM
temleh sih fo ecnelis eht ni