.nirg a htiw smra sih dessorc eh
.s’looC ta tsuj ton dna -- sgig teg ot detrats ew yllautnevE“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,edniM JT yb
.denmad eb redneG .ekil si xes tahw s’tahT“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,deunitnoc netram ehT
.taeb a gnissim tuohtiw ,drawrof gnicaf
…os tsuj s’ti ,teem spih nehw dna ,dnirg dna pmub uoY
.kcub eht ot deddon dahC ”.ffuc eht ffo
”.ekiM ,thginot mih teem ll’uoY .dneirfyob yM“
,eno sa dehgis yehT
yrots siH .modnaf eht ni seigolohtna rehto fo rebmun a dna ,taeH
.gnilims llits ,niaga
.daeh sih koohs etoyoc ehT
sih htiw ni denioj luaS nehT“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
;hctip dna enot eht dekcehc eh sa mot a gninut ekil tsomla saw tI
”.ytraM ,em htiw eerga dluow-- elpoep lla fo -- uoy thguoht I ,gniyas saw I sa ,tuB“
.gnilims ,kcub eht dettaws netram eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.llew os gnittif si gnihtyreve gniwonk fo htmraw tahT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.dahC ot ecnalg gnol dils a htiw dias luaS
,dehgis netram enip ehT ”.WV ruo tub
”?negawskloV a gniyalp ekil xes s’woH“ .dias ekiM
,dnuora swap sih devaw eh ”,dna erup
tsuj erew ew dna esool dna hgih saw ygrene ehT
.deilper netram eht ”,luaS ,revetahW“
.ekiM ot kcab denrut dna
.su rof ereht neeb s’ehS“
.eciov y-ssab ,wol
”.yzarc ekil ’nicnuob sub eht tog I“ .delims ytraM
”,nuf saw ti tub ,lacisum dednuos ton evah yam tI
.srehto eht ta dekool dna
wap etalocohc a debbur eH
”.xes tuoba enola tel -- draeh reve ev’I snosirapmoc tseddo eht fo eno si tahT“
.ytraM ot luaS morf dekool netram ehT
”!thgin taht rebmemer I ,haey hO“
ot woh wenk uoY .nehw tif dluow tahw wenk
”,gnileef taht dnA“
.taeb a tuo gnippat detrats adnap der eht ,elkcuhc a htiW
”.taf kcaZ llac ot gniyrt uoy sselnU .nav a enola tel
.deddon luaS ”.laicepS“
”.negawskloV a gniyalp ekiL“
-- ti otni worg uoy tub
.deksa etoyoc yknal a ”?kcaZ s’ohW“
.elims a htiw daeh sih dniheb sdnah sih deppuc eh sa
si yrots s’yadoT dna
fo ytirup ehT
”.sub eht tog ew nehT
”?yug dnuos ruoy m’I esuac‘ taht em llac ot evah yllaer uoy oD“ .dehgis etoyoc ehT
”?luaS ,sreltna ruoy gniyalp detrats dna kcab devom eh
.sisahpme htiw draobhsad eht kcurts eh sa ,dias ytraM
.rosiv nus eht ,tser mra eht ,swodniw eht ,hsad eht
.no skcits ruoy teg nac uoy gnihtyreve dna gnihtyna no gnikconk ,dnuora lla decnuob uoY“
,edam ti dnuos tahw wenk uoY
.nosinu ni dias eerht rehto eht ”,puY“
.adnap der eht ot dekool dahC
,tsrif ta drawkwa ro driew s’tI
,etoyoc eht depacse rethgual fo trons a sA
.daeh sih deddon dna delims ekiM
,gig a ot rab eht morf ro ,rab eht ot snoisses maj ruo morf gnivird erew luaS ro em rehtie fI“
”,thgir s’taht ,tihS“ ”.demmaj
.gniyalp s’remmurd eht demim netram enip ehT
,redneg rof tpecxe tuB“
.taht rebmemer I ,doG“
,tih eb dluoc taht ecafrus a dah ti fI
”,yllaretil ,elpoep emoS“
”.ytraM ,thgin taht gnihtyreve dna gnihtyna attuo cisum nettog ev’d’uoY“
”,did ew ,haey lleH“ ”.retteb tog eW
”,etib ll’I ,thgi’A“
”.rehto hcae revo gnippirt dna ysmulc erew ew ,su denioj ekiM erofeb lleW“
dehgis nitram enip ehT
.tuoba ’niklat saw I tahw si“
,thgil der taht ta rebmemer“
.nuf llits saw ti
”negawskloV a gniyalP ekiL“:yojne esaelP
.delims nitram enip ehT
.nageb kaeuqs-dna-mhtyhr railimaf eht sa rae na dekcilf dahC
.deddon netram enip ehT .dias ytraM
,GNAF ni dehsilbup neeb s’ohw renniW drawA yraretiL oeL a ,edniM JT yb
.taht rebmemer I ,tihS“ ”.did eh
.redluohs sih deppalc dna revo dehcaer kcub ehT ”?ynnuf os s’tahW“
.hsad eht no gnirettel desiar eht tsniaga
.srepiw eht no deppilf luaS
,detrats dleihsdniw eht tsniaga niar fo rettap eht nehW
tsuj ew dnA .’nippord erew owt uoy taeb eht pu dekcip I tub
.erom rehtegot evoorg uoy ,ekil yeht tahw wonk uoy sA .eno otni worg
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,sgniht wen tuo gniyrt er’uoy ,rentrap wen a htiW
.noisses maj rehtona ekil adnik ,htrof dna kcab tsuJ
,WV yna fo gnikaeps t’nsaw I ,taht dias I nehw dnA
”.tniop a evah uoy sseug I“
”negawskloV a gniyalP ekiL“
”.skcits sih tuo llup dna
,elcihev yna ekil eb dluoc yug a woh ees t’nod I
.ecnelis ni yromem yppah eht fo gnikniht
”,negawskloV a gniyalp
,adnap der eht ot gnitniop dias dahC
.uoy rof skrow tahw dna meht rof skrow tahw gniees
.mih htiw dehgual srehto ehT
”.emosewa saw hsur ragus a no ekil dnuora ecnuob uoy gniees dnA“
”negawskloV a gniyalP ekiL“ saw sihT
.thguoht yppah ni taes sih otni depmuls dna
.mih dniheb eidaor eht gnicaf ,dnuora denrut dna ,delims dahC .delbmum eh
.niaga ffo dednuos srepiw eht thgil der a ot pu meht dellup ytraM sA
”,ekoj a fo trats eht ekil sdnuoS“
ekil s’tI“   edniM JT yb
.ytraM ot bmuht a detniop dahC
taes s’regnessap eht ni kcab gnihcterts ,dias dahC
.taes sih ni tnemeticxe erom htiw decnuob adnap der ehT
dehgis eH ”.lla ti fo ssen-su eht …eht dnA .tnemom eht
.adnap der eht ta detniop dna
.enizagam
.delkcuhc yeht sa seye sih dellor ekiM
”?namow a ekil rac a tuoba deklat reven ev’uoY“
”.sub eht gnola lla pat mih raeh d’ew
etna eht deppu ,nugtohs gnidir ,ytraM nehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
-- vorpmi tsuJ .gnola gnivird elihw seton emos tuo gnimmuh detrats I
.daeherof sih ot dnah a gnisserp ,delkcuhc luaS
.efil ym fo sthgin tseb eht fo eno saw taht ,eduD“
,steg mot ro erans a ecnuob eht evah t’ndid I“
doow xuaf eht tsniaga sregnif sih gnippat
ecnarbmemer fo pans a htiw dedda kcub eht
”,won ,gniyas er’uoy tahw teg I“
”etacinruF“ ’sserP terreF deR ni deraeppa tsrif
”.efil fo lluf erew seciov ruO .ti gnileef
,ni depmuj dahC ”,hO“ ”.reh yalp
”.wonk mih gnittel rof sknahT“
.t’nia ti tub ,seod tI“
pu tas nitram enip ehT .gnihgual
,llits tuB“ .daeh sih koohs dahC
.leehw eht dniheb morf derewsna adnap der eht ”,evah I“
”?maj ot detrats tsrif ew nehw rebmemeR
.tnedifnoc erom tog yllautneve ew dnA
.yalp ot ydaer dna taerg gnileef lla erew su fo eerht eht -- siht ekil thgin yniar a no -- raey tsal nehT“
.drow a rof gnihcaer
detrats nem eerht rehto eht erofeb sub rieht fo bac eht dellif ecneliS