srac gnikool evisnepxe htiw dellif saw level egarag ehT
.snottub sti ta gnikop nageb dna pu ecived tsirw sih detfil eh
,etuor wol eht rof detpo eh daetsnI
.etelpmoc saw gat lluf eht dna
emit retfa emit gnidnif
.tiusrup toh ni draug eht htiw ,pmar eht pu kcab gnitnirps dna gninrut erofeb flow denam eht delworg
.gninnur ot denruter daetsni dna
.draug eht detrats
.mih fo edis rehtie ot sgnidliub eciffo eht fo stnediser emityad eht tub
egde eht revo dekool neht eH
deppots draug ehT
.ni emoc dah eh yaw eht sa desrevart ylisae sa t’nsaw yaw rehto eht yella ralucitrap siht rof tub
noitcejorp eht dniheb tops gnidih sih morf noitasrevnoc eht fo emos draehrevo uraT
,egdel eht no ydaerla saw uraT
.esolc ylralucitrap saw revo gnidliub txen eht
egdirb eht htaenrednu gniws dna ot no barg dluoc
.yrd dna ecin saw mih fo tnorf ni gnidliub eciffo eht fo llaw eht naem did ti tub
,txen eht neht dna ,ynoclab txen eht ot deppoh dna
denepo egdirb eht fo edis raf eht no srood eht sa gnibmilc nageb eH
.enot ffurg a htiw dias eh
ti ssorca dehsur eH
.mih woleb seinoclab fo wor erom eno saw ereht taht was dna
.ydob a rof gnikool krow ot tnew lortap revir eht sa erehwesle tnemetats a gnitteg devres retteb eb dluow yeht taht dnA
,werc sih fo taht dna lobmys lanosrep sih dedulcni hcihw
.raelc saw tsaoc eht erus saw eh litnu tiaw dluow eh erehT
dezilaer eh ,melborp a eb ot gnitrats saw yella siht fo dne ehT
.gnigniws hcum sa eriuqer t’ndid taht
.noitautis sih kcehc ot deppots eh sa
,negramxirF .R.W yb
,draug rumel eht morf sesirprus erom fo yraW
denrut flow denam eht sa revewoh gniklat deppots eH
,egdel eht gnola llits yaw sih gnikam yllausac saw rumel eht taht was dna redluohs sih revo decnalg eH
.egarag eht fo tuo dna nwod pmar eht gniraen saw uraT dna
.yella eht ni gnidnal elbatrofmocnu rehtar a rof nwod erom ecno neht dna
,retfa detrats neht dna dehgis draug ehT
efil ot emac mih erofeb llaw ehT
gniliar eht revo deromalc eh
,revir eht otni depmuj dah tcepsus eht ylekil taht denimreted saw ti ylkciuq dnA
fo dnuos eht raeh ot nageb eH
,txen eht neht dnA
ti rednu flesmih gnignilf
rumel eht deksa ”?enod eW“
.erom ecno egdel eht no pu bmilc ot
.gniyarps nageb dna llaw eht ta elttob eht detniop flow denam ehT
.egdel a ot ecnatsid emos pu flesmih llup dna otno barg ot mih rof hguone tsuJ
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.saw taht sa esiwnu sa
.weiv fo tuo tsuj ,egdirb eht fo edis eht ni pag llams eht ni efas
,tsiaw sih ot elttob eht gninruteR
.teerts eht no kcab saw eh dna
pu flesmih dellup uraT
.neeb dah flow denam eht erehw ot esolc emac eh sa egdirb eht fo edis eht revo kool ot nageb dna
gnola rehtruf elttil A
redrah flesmih dehsup draug ehT
.egap ytiniffaruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
draug eht was dna selop galf eerht eht fo elddim eht ot dekool eH
.ruoh siht rof lamron naht reivaeh niaga saw hcihw
.ni degagne saw flow denam eht scitna detacilpmoc erom eht htiw gnirehtob ton
.eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo tnemevom dettops eh
,reusrup sih fo lufdniM
.taorht sih deraelc draug ehT
negramxirF .R.W yb
”,em gniddik eb attog uoY“
.htap s’uraT otni thgir tixe eht evoba egdel a morf tpael draug eht sa
.rumel eht decaptuo ylisae flow denam llat eht tub
woleb ecnartne eht evobA
.og ot yaw eht saw pu dediced ylkciuq os dna
rood raf eht ta erew yeht emit eht yb tub egdirb eht ssorc ot dedeecorp yehT
,tnew eh emit erom eno gniliar eht revO
draug eht fo liat gnol yllausunu eht dettops eh sa
drawrof htap siht no sucof sih tpek eh
retal sriats fo sthgilf owT
.dekcol saw edisni yaw sih taht
,gnimrof saw eh gat ehT
.ti pota dednal dnah
.nwod decnalg neht uraT
.gnizag eht ni erahs ot
.drawrof yaw a dnif ot yrt ot dnuora dekool eH
stnirps thgiarts gnikam
s’uraT rof ,gnag lavir a ta detegrat toN
,gniliar egdirb eht no pu debmilc ,dehgis uraT
.driht eht no gnigniws saw eh dna
.noitacol sih ot senord ecilop eht nommus ot ecived a gnitarepo
rehtona neht dna ,nrut rehtonA
.dnuob elgnis a ni level egarag eht ot pu tpael draug eht sa tsol saw rumel eht gninnurtuo yb pu edam dah uraT emit eht lla ,revewoH
.dekcol erew ynoclab tsrif eht fo srood eht tub
.kcul on dah tub seinoclab erom wef a deirt uraT
.uraT dniheb thgir dednal eh sa
.sepirts sti lla dna
,ciffart rac eht naht rehto detresed saw egdirb ehT
,retal dooh s’xof desserd llew emos revo edils eno dna sllac esolc wef A
flow enam eht sa llat sa enoemos neve erehwon dnA
,wodniw eht fo weiv lluf ni deraeppa noitcejorp eulb ro der thgirb ,wen a emit hcaE
dettops eh mih gniwollof tey erugif a saw erehT
.oot edis rehto eht no swodniw eht dna
tniap eht edisni senihcam onan eht gnignarra ,etavitca dna
.teef sih no kcab saw eh noos dna
.yella eht ni enola regnol on saw eh taht dezilaer uraT taht emit siht tuoba revewoh saw tI
edaf ot nageb revewoh elims siH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
retrohs hcni na saw eh fI
yaw sih dellorts eh sa flesmih gnicnalab ylluferac
ti fo pot revo tluav ot mih rof ysae ylevitaler saw ti ,toof xis revo llew gnieB
.ti bmilc ot gniyrt elbatrofmoc leef ot flow denam eht rof strap gnivom ynam oot dah tI
.ecnef knil niahc sti dna
.metsys eht ot ecneivresbus rieht rof meht gnikcom
,ciffart htiw ysub yllausunu saw dna
.htrof dna kcab gnigniws saw eh noos tub
retal sgniws elpuoc A
.egdirb yks a otno egarag eht morf tixe evitanretla eht koot eh dna
remmihs ot nageb llaw eht no edam dah eh skram elbisivni eht os did eh sA
.ti gnibbarg yllufsseccus ,txen eht rof dehcaer dna elop eht fo og tel eh ,drawrof gnuws eh sA
.edih ot deirt dna
,revresbo lausac eht oT
.raelc demees rettam deyarps eht
.tcapmi ro sehsalps fo ngis oN .flow denam oN
,gninnur tpek dna renroc eht dednuor uraT
retal skram lanif wef A
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
mih ot txen pu dellup senord ehT
.sedis sih ot dekool eH
.yawa owt ro elim emos sreciffo laer eht yb nur ylekil dna
.llet ot yrots gniticxe na htiw esuoh efas eht ot denruter d’eh neht dnA
,llaw eht no wodniw tsewol eht ta tsirw sih detniop neht eH
.revir eht fo ssenkcalb ykni eht ylno saw woleb tuB
.seinoclab fo seires a saw ereht erehw ylralucitraP
,pu seirots elpuoc a llits
daehrevo dils sgnikrow sti fo seohce duol ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.ylreporp dnob ot nac sih fo stnetnoc eht rof hguone yrD
.gnidliub eht fo renroc eht dnuora
woleb dekrap selcihev enord eht fo seroc etomer eht erew stobor ehT
.ssorc etiuq saw ohw ,rumel eht htiw noitasrevnoc eht saw ereht neht dnA
llewriats eht fo rood eht deraen eh sa woleb morf sneris enord ecilop
.dniheb stobor elbmin os ton eht tfel gnivah renroc eht gnidnuor saw draug eht ,detcepxe eh sA
yrenihcam fo eceip egral A .ti deraen eh sa
.mih dniheb dekool eh neht dnA
.teerts eht ot yaw eht gnikcolb draug ytiruces gnikool desaelpsid rehtar eht ot ezag sih derewol eH
,retfa detrats draug ehT
si yrots s’yadot dna
.woleb revir cixot eht otni gnillaf dna pirg rieht gnisol ylekil tuohtiw
”.serugiF .rumel A“
yella eht fo dne eht dehcaer noos uraT
”wohS thgiL elttiL“:yojne esaelP
,sreknab dna srekrow eciffo eht yb dettops eb ot ydaer
.yella eht nwod tnirps ot nageb dna
.erofeb pmuj taht devivrus dah eno on ,lla retfA
.srotcejorp orcim lanoitcnuf otni
.klawedis eht nwod tnirps lluf a otni tnew dna
”…uoy era ro ecin yalp ot gniog uoy era woN“
,detcepxe eh naht erom truh elop tsrif eht gnibbarG   .tpael uraT
dehsinav revewoh epacse fo sthguoht siH
,deeps pu kcip ot nageb uraT sa tub
.elop galf txen eht no gnisucofer erofeb rumel gnihcaorppa eht ta decnalg eH
,niaga gnidliub eht no hctac d’eh os drawrof gniws txen eht no tuo gel a dnetxe ot saw
.edis raf eht no yrenihcam fo eceip egral eht otno dna
,negramxirF .R.W yb
.teerts eht ssorca llewriats eht edistuo tsuj pu gnillup senord eht gnissentiw
.niaga pael ot pu gniydaer saw dnA
egdirb eht fo edis eht debbarg evah dluoc yrrauq sih erehw tops a rof gnikool dnuora daeh sih denarc eH
.egarag gnikrap eht ot ssecca mih evig dluow taht
.dezilaer eh erutcetihcra detacilpmoc dah egdirb yks eht fo dne taht no gnidliub ehT
.wodniw eht fo tnorf ni deraeppa gat sih fo noitcejorp gninnips a dna
”wohS thgiL elttiL“ saw sihT
.dniheb rumel eht evael ot nageb eh
.level taht no swodniw eht fo tser eht kram ot nageb dna
.edis eht revo tnew dna
.niaga ecno yrd gnieb ot yaw sti no llew saw ytic eht dna ylecin pu deraelc dah yks eht tub ,yad taht reilrae deniar dah tI
”,em deciton uoy emit tuobA“
,rewsna ot rehtob t’ndid uraT
.htaenrednu gnitnuat fo tib elttil a dna spool ytilauQ
,snoitacilbuP laoG yb dnaH a flesruoY eviG ni hcnarB kaO etorw ohw dna
,nar eh egarag eht pU
.htap evitanretla eht gnola epacse ot ytiliba sih tuoba tnedifnoc tlef eh ,llitS
.edis eht revo dekool dna
snoitrop deleehw rieht morf delevarnu stobor eht dna
.nottub tcejorp eht dekcilc dna
,pu hctac ot gnilggurts
egdel fo tib txen eht otno pu flesmih dellup eh sA
mih dniheb egdel eht no dednal draug eht erofeb gnola sretem wef a ylno gnitteg
gnisrevart siht fo trap lanif ehT
.erutcurts eht fo renroc eht ni llewriats eht rof gnimia ylkciuq
.flow denam eht rof ykcirt
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
egdel eht otno pu llup a ereht morf dnA
revir eht revo egdirb eht sdrawot denrut eH
egarevel hguone tsuj mih gniwolla
.os od ot regae llits tub
,etercnoc fo esnapxe dilos a fo
,gnineve ralucitrap siht ni flesmih dnuof uraT yella eht ni selddup t’nerew ereht naem t’ndid tahT
,puorg fo tros taht t’nsaw werc
.ylecin pu gnimrof saw
,egdel eht gnola evom ot nageb dna
.enihcam eht rednu pag worran a hguorht gnidils dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.retfa gnola ymmihs ot detrats yletaidemmi neht dna
drawrof yaw elbissop a ees ot dethgiled saw dna gnidliub eht fo renroc txen eht dednuor uraT
,stros suoirav fo ssendam dna if-ics snwaps ohw
.ylgums uraT dias ”,ereht olleh yhW“
.lanoitan dna lacol ,srennab lufroloc fo rebmun a gnitrops selop galf fo seires a saw
”wohS thgiL elttiL“
.hcaer ot elba neeb ton evah d’eh
,uraT rof eussi na eb ton dluow siht yllamroN
,tiusrup toh ni llits ,rumel ehT
.tuo dehcram ,stobor ladepib owt yb dewollof ,draug eht dna
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
,ynoclab txen eht otno nwod gnippord
.etercnoc eht ni seloh egral ylsuoixonbo gnidiova dna egabrag revo gnippoh
.woleb egdirb eht fo erutcurts etercnoc dilos dna sredrig eht saw was eh lla tuB
delims flow denam ehT
.noitautis eht fo weiv tnereffid yrev a mih evag sessalg s’uraT revewoH
,egdirb yks eht fo edis eht revo dekool uraT
.erom ecno sneris fo sdnuos eht raeh ot nageb eh sa egdirb eht fo elddim eht dehcaer uraT
.htap sih gnikcolb saw yawa gnigguhc
.dekcol yleruces edis raf eht no srood eht dnif ot ylno
,hguone ylisae pmuj siht edam uraT
,mih dniheb raf oot ton dednal draug ehT
.reparcsyks eht rof llah yrtne egral a fo egde eht ta dedne egdel eht litnu