,ot dediced ew dna slrig eht htiw gniklat saw I
.gnitadimitni ro tluciffid oot mees t'ndid taht gnihtemos rof gnikool
tnemtrapa sih fo wodniw eht tuo lwoh emosenol sih morf gnihtyreve tuoba meht dlot eh
.raey eht nihtiw decnuonna eb ylekil lliw noitcnitxe  eht taht em smrofni ecruos A
.bulc eritne eht tif ot moor hguone egral a ni sruoh owt rof tsinoitpecer eht diap haraS
".deneppah tsuj fo tros tI
,seiceps eht rettam on ,selpoep tneipas ew taht eveileb t'nod I
.smelborp dna seirots rieht htiw hsem ot ni efil nwo sih fo setodcena gniworht
.yadirF no kcolc'o xis ta krow retfa keew yreve tem yehT
.lladnaR rof moor yna t'nsaw ereht erehw
,ylimaf eht htiw efirts gnisuac saw gnilbis hcihw
,rewols tlef emiT
.roolf eht ot derettalc
.taht ekil gnilwoh nees eb reve dluow flow dezilivic on taht dias ylnrets dna ,rae eht yb edisni mih deggard
.engapmahc fo elttob a ekil pu denepo eH
htnom taht ni erom delwoh eH
"- dna eciton ecnabrutsid esion a tog I  .srallod derdnuh owt deen I ,llew ,I"
.tnaw dna gnignol dna
.tnatnuocca elgnis ylenol a fo efil eht fo sgnihton eht ni detseretni taht lla t'nerew dna
.stnap sserd sih fo tekcop eht otni peed ti deffuts dna
,enohp sih rof gnilbmuts mih werht cinap fo egrus A
.deunitnoc lladnaR os
TRC yklub eht revo ylsuovren gnicnalg
"!tfel eht no moor eht s'ti dna rood taht hguorht era sriatS  .setunim wef a ni gnitrats eb dluohs yehT  !thgir s'tahT"
,devlos morf emoc dluow enif rallod derdnuh owt eht erehw fo melborp neddus eht dna ot klat ot sdneirf htiW
.ahpla eht sa reh dekram yllatnem lladnaR
.lamina llams a llik ot monev hguone dleh hsuhs s'reed ehT
".hguoht ,seirots ruoy fo yna sa gnitseretni sa eb ll'ti kniht t'nod I
.dehtoot-kcub dna ,thgirb
"?ksa ot hsiw uoy taht ti si tahW
.ytivitpac ni yawa dessap sah
.niaga yks thgin eht ot gnis dna
.7 lennahc no oga sthgin owt ,yllautca yrots swen a saw tI"
.eromyna ti ni t'nsaw eh
?snevaeh eht ot seton llirhs dna doolb ni dnuob
,senildaed ym tem dna boj ym enod syawla ev'I
,llaf dna esir dluow eciov sih yaw eht
pohs eeffoc eht ot deklaw ylksirb eh ,reward ksed sih ni gab eht gnihsats dna
.thgir os tlef tI
.llew sa srae reed lacinoc gnikcilf reh fo dooh eht rednu niks eht denekrad hsulb elbitpecrepmi tsomla nA
,ylrae ruoh retrauq a ereht meht fo htfif a ylno ,nemow ehT
.deddon eH   .deksa neraK
.noitnetta yap t'ndid eh tsrif tA
,daeh sih koohs eH
tsae eht ot skcolb lareves puorg eht del ehS
.raelc saw daeh siH
.sriatsnwod dnuora gnittis lla erew nemow eht
!ereh er'uoY"  .demialcxe ehs  "!lladnaR"
,eluY taht uoy mrofni ot terger eW  .thgir s'tahT"
"?ti deen uoy od yltcaxe yhw dna deen uoy od ecnavda fo tros tahW
.semag draob dna nray fo sretsulc drazahpah htiw dekcats erew
ssenesolc kcap a
;sevil s'rehto hcae tuoba gnihtyreve wonk ot demees nemow ehT
tops ytpme eht rof eceip elzzup a saw ssenesolc tahT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.kcatta traeh a t'nsaw siht ,oN
.retsalp dna kcirb hguorht ees t'ndluoc eh taht noom eht ot tuo gnas eh sa ecaf sih no noisserpxe eht dootsrednu yeht ,revewoH
,ruoh txen eht revO
.gnihtaerb sih deidaets dna tnemom a rof llits dleh eH
mih edisni peed neddih dleh d'eh snoitome dna sgnileef fo efas eht no kcoldap detsur eht
"!em wollof ,no emoC
,sknaht kciuq a deddon flow ehT
.traeh s'lladnaR ni
.enihcam ekoarak eht dellortnoc taht elosnoc ekil-telbat elttil eht rof barg t'ndid ehs ,revewoH  ".lliw
.yawyna mih reetnulov d'yeht tseggus sevren sih tub
,aruaL nehw gnorw saw gnihtemos fi ksa ot tuoba saw eH
gniliec eht ta pu detniop elzzum s'eod eht ,daetsnI
.mrof tseuqer emitrevo na tuo gnillif tneps saw emitrevo fo ruoh flah tsrif ehT
.keew yreve sdneirf htiw pissog ot esucxe na gnivah tuoba saw tI
.deggar dna trohs detnap eH
.eganam dluoc eh sa elbatneserp dna hserf sa eb ot redro ni krow retfa tnecs sih yfituaeb dna
.ekat ot thgir eb dluow
,dias flow eht ",yeH"   ".doog ,hO"
",nwod tnew yllaer ti woh mih dlot uoy fi dnatsrednu d'eh dna ,yrots eht raeh t'ndid eH  .ssob ruoy ot klat yllautca ot deen uoy ,kooL"
sgnithgis flow fo sgnitnuocca nwo rieht htiw ni nettirw evah sreweiv ruo fo ynam
.mirg era sgnidnif rieht tub
.deneppah tahw uoy gnillet saw I nehw yrots lluf eht uoy evig ot elba t'nsaw I"
,tahw wonk uoy - wonk uoy dnA
.yawhguorht niam eht morf nwod srenroc lareves teertskcab a no pu dedne yehT
.rof erew seud bulc tahw saw siht taht dias dna
esle enoemos llet ot detnaw eh dezilaer eh nehw detaropave neht tub
.tsrif eht naht railimaf erom dna
.swap gnilbmuf sih ot dehctalnu wodniw tnemtrapa eht ,lortnoc fo ssol hsirevef ro tcnitsni hguorhT
.gnol oot rof efil elats sih ni kcuts neeb d'eh taht
.esolc oot saw thgir sih no mar ehT
,sevlow fo stsaeb ylrub derutaef egap-bew rieht no detsop serutcip eht lla tub
?ekil tlef kcatta traeh a tahw siht sI
yenom ynapmoc eht gnitsoc yllaitnetop ,snoitaluclac yralas ym ot sruoh dda dluow I ,enim fo eeyolpme na yb edam noisiced enani yreve rof revoc ot erew I fI
,tius gnigguh ylthgit sih ffo ekat ot gnirehtob toN  .dias eh ",kcuF"
.sreparcsyks dna steerts ytic eht hguorht riapsed deohce taht lwoh a esool tel eh dna
!eunitnoC  !sey ,seY"   "?riS"
.yadseuT no nettog d'eh esaeler fo tib elttil eht retfa yllaicepsE
,sroolf tsrif gnidworc spohs hciwdnas dna spohs eeffoc eht dna
,traeh yvaeh a htiw ydegart siht weiv I hguohtlA
.llew sa emitrevo evitcaorter evorppa ot traeh esuom lacinahcem sih ni erehwemos ti dnif dluow ssob sih taht depoh eh sa
".thgir erew uoy ,sdneirf er'ew ,haeY  !sdneirf er'eW"  .detcejretni lladnaR "!oN"
mih dniheb rood eht tuhs ylkciuq eh tub ,taeh htiw dehsulf elzzum dna srae siH
.yhtomiT ot klat ot ni dellac gnitteg saw eh naht
pohs eeffoc nedoow gnimussanu na fo roolf dnoces eht no
htnom rehtona rof eud t'nerew taht smrof xat tuo gnillif yb tnew owt rehtonA
?efil fo seiteixna dna niap eht esaeler ot mih ekil tsuj gnis yeht diD
sgnidliub eciffo suoenegomoh eht fo daetsnI
.ecalp eht rof leef a teg dluoc eh taht os yadsruhT taht emithcnul gnirud pohs eeffoc eht yb deppots eH
,sruf yerg laudividni gnol eht ta derats eH
".sevlow suoucav owt eseht neewteb naht
.siht ekil mih ees ot dnuora t'nsaw mom sih tsael tA
.sgnilwoh fo secnatsni ro
.dehgual ydal peehs a
.lwoh sih fo eton prahs raelc eht desaeler dna
.eunitnoc ot flesmih decrof eh os
.deb sih otno despalloc flow eht
.mih pord tsuj dluohs ehs taht reh dlot ,aneyh nekopstuo na ,neraK
.erofeb siht ekil gnihtemos rof deksa reven ev'I dna
,gnissarrabme oot raf eb dluow lwoh rehtonA
.mih hguorht thgir nrub ot gniog erew slaoc toh ekil tlef ti elihw nwod gniyal peek ot elbissopmi saw tI
.rood eht denepo neht dna
.deb sih morf pu tog eH
lladnaR morf elcric eht dnuora yawflah raeb nworb A
.enif s'ti ,yllaeR"
.pu deppots eb t'ndluoc seye s'flow eht dniheb setagdoolf ehT
.yldab taht flesmih ssarrabme t'ndluow eh taht gniyarp
.dias lladnaR ",melborp on s'tI"
;ti ot erom ereht saw rO
".haeY"  .decniw lladnaR
.tehcorc eht no saw noitnetta sih fo sucof eht ,ylnekatsiM
,pu worht ot gniog saw eh fi derednow eh ,tnemom a roF
,tekcaj tius sih htooms ,ruf sih mirt ot
.dnah reh desiar elcric riahc eht fo edis raf eht no reed A
.seibboh on dah eh ,revewoH
.dootsrednu lladnaR ,revewoH
,skcod eht yb rab a ta syadsruhT no tem eno tseraen ehT
eciton eht delpmurc eh ,yteixna fo tuob laitini na retfA
.mih tcive ot sthgir s'droldnal eht nihtiw llew saw ti
sreeb dah ew tuB  ?sdneirf ton ew erA  ?taht daersim I diD"  ?daeh sih fo tlit thgils a htiw retupmoc sih morf pu dekool dna gnipyt deppots esuom ehT   "?tahW"
".gniyas erew uoy sa
.gnitadimitni t'nsaw depoh eh taht yaw a ni elzzum sih gnihcterts elims tnahpmuirt a htiw bulc tehcorc eht otni deklaw lladnaR
.yawa edih ot stixe ycnegreme eht raen renroc elbatrofmocnu ,dewodahs a flesmih dnuof eh netfO
.yawa dnah reh nekat t'ndah haraS
,elzzum sih no demrof nirg A
,mih detalutargnoc ,ediw delims ehS
,tnemtrapa ffo desolc sih ni deb tfos sih no nwod dial lladnaR nehw ,revewoH
.ytic eht deteknalb ydaerla dah ksud
,emoh rof detrats eh emit eht yB
.erew swodniw eht ni sesserd eht yduag ylbirret woh tuoba sdneirf sih htiw hgual dluoc eh nehw dab sa t'nsaw ti tuB
.yadot tnereffid gnihtemos od d'ew taht gnikniht saw I os ,yeH
.derevihs lladnaR
?kcehcyap txen ym no ecnavda na em gnivig redisnocer esaelp uoy dluoW
.sgel sih neewteb liat sih htiw eciffo eht tfel lladnaR
.woleb seirots neves daor ysub eht fo selbmur dna ,sehceercs ,slworg eht edisgnola
.smra sih ni elzzum sih deirub eH
.wap s'lladnaR no dnah a tes ehs
!klat mih teL  !wen s'eH"
.lliw I" ,dias haraS
.wohemos esool ti tel dna evlav eht nrut ot dah I dna ,tnev maets a ekil em fo edisni pu gnillew erusserp siht lla saw erehT
,mih sa ylrae sa pu wohs ot enoyreve rof lamron t'nsaw tI
,haraS saw denrael eh eman esohw ,reed eht dna delttes tog yeht retfA
seilppus moorhtab fo lluf gab a ni thguorb eh ,yadirF nO
,etunim txen eht rof gnihtyna dias eno oN
.swen cigart siht gnorw evorp ot tpmetta na ni pleh ruoy etaicerppa ew ,llitS
,ksed s'miT no rotinom
.yenom eht detnaw eh taht t'nsaw tI
.meht ni owt ro yrots gnitseretni na tog s'enoyrevE  !taht yas t'noD"
,stpiecer fo naeco na rednu tekcop sih ni deirub
pihsnoinapmoc detulidnu fo elpmaxe retteb a dnif nac
.mih htiw gnola thgir hgual ot meht rof dna
".haeY"  .derevihs lladnaR
.won sraey 3 rof uoy rof gnikrow neeb ev'I ,yawyna tuB"
.dehsaw ti evah ot droffa dluoc eh litnu nilonal ekil llems ot gniog t'nsaw taoc tius sih taht deyarp eh dna
,dezilaer ylkciuq eh ,bulc tehcorC
rettOtnacifingiS yb
.gnieb llew sih rof kcis deirrow neeb evah dluow ehS
.detnaw eh tahw dna mih tuoba neeb tsuj syawla dah tI
.kcap a dedeen eh taht dediced lladnaR
.surohc eht no ni denioj
.noitcennoc regaem tsal taht gnisol raeb t'ndluoc eH
,niaga taht yrt reve ot erew eh fi taht mih demrofni yletilop tpircstsop A
.htiw teb taht ekam dluoc eh enoemos rof dehsiw eH
,rof detnuocca eb dluoc lla taht etacidni snoitagitsevni pu-wollof ruo ,revewoH
.delbmert eH  ".em ot snaem siht hcum woh aedi on evah lla uoy - uoY
.msaisuhtne gnimoclew htiw mih deteerg
,spets wef a koot
,lausu sa ylrae ,pohs eeffoc eht otni deklaw eh nehW
.sraey neethgie rof ffo dleh eh ,sdrawretfA
.thgin ta sllac reh gninruter neeb t'ndah dneirfyob reh woh tuoba deklat
si yrots s’yadot dna
,denmad eb sepytoeretS
"?tehcorc rof ereh er'uoY"
,hctits cisab a hguorht swap ydaetsnu sih dediug
esion etihw llord eht hguorht raeps ronet gnicreip ,prahs a
.tekcop sih otni kcab enohp eht dils ylwols eH
.enoyna ot timda ot evah t'ndluow eh erehw flesmih edisni peed lwarc ot gnitnaw
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
?elbatius erom eb ton yadirF
.ssob sih htiw dah eh klat eht detnuocer yldeticxe eh
,dekcarc dna deniarts sdroc lacov siH
".doog nmad yllaer tlef ti
,mraw tub enola saw eH
reisae saw keew dnoces ehT     .detpecca
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.pu kcuf eht tuhs ot evoba wodniw a morf delley enoemoS
esle enoemos ot txen gnittis yb tuoba thguorb ssenesolc fo noisulli ehT
.thgin suoiverp eht ecnabrutsid cilbup eht rof
.xaler dluoc eh ekil tlef yllanif eh
.pal sih no thgit rehtegot dekcol swap s'flow ehT
,aneyh eht ,neraK emit tsrif eht
.slirtson sih fo lortnoc rof tnemevap no nus fo hcnets luof eht htiw gnithgif ,lacol dna ngierof
redluohs dna mra sih tsniaga deltsur loow ehT
,dluoc eh sa gnol sa eton eht dleh eH
.seye sih rednu ruf eht dettam taht sraet eht dniheb gninaem eht wenk yehT
.htnom tsal revef a ot debmuccus ohw
noitacidni na eb ot taht deredisnoc I  .ruoh yppah yadirF a rof oga shtnom eerht
.roolf tsrif eht no nwod tiaw ot meht rof ton ylniatrec dna
.elims ynnus reh gnikaerb yliratnemom neve tuohtiw deraperp tibbar eht hcihw aet enimsaj a rof diap dna kcab denrut eh ,deretsulF
.bulc tehcorc eht fo nemow eht ni edifnoc ot doog yllaer tlef tI
,ot tnaw t'ndluow eh wonk ot hguone llew mih wenk yehT
,gniklat saw eh nehw tniop emos tA
,kcap esolc a sa tuo gnuh dna rehtegot delwoh yeht fi nevE
.detseggus xof citcra eht
.esaenu dna noitatcepxe
.dehcnelc taorht sih dna
.moor ekoarak foorpdnuos ,llams eht ni deohce flow eht fo gnos psirc eht "!oooowA
!flow suoucav tsal ehT"   "-wonk uoy ,saw eh
.tuo mih kcik ot retal stnemom ni emoc meht evah ot ylno taes s'esle enoemos laets yllatnedicca ot tnaw t'ndid eH
".taht ekil uoy no pu lla tog I ezilaer t'ndid dna ffo dezod" ,elims citegolopa na htiw dias mar eht ",yrroS"
.delwoh yllatnedicca I dna hcum oot saw gnihtyreve erehw tnemom gnissarrabme siht dah tsuj I
,elbanigami seiceps yreve fo sksum eht htiw evisserppo ti dnif ot desu eH
.lladnaR ni aibohportsualc dlim a dellitsni
.maercs ot detnaw eH  .nur ot detnaw eH
"?ton ew era ,sdneirf era eW
ssarg nehsa gniyd fo sedalb
,puorg eht htiw gnola depissog ylippah eH
".sruoh gnipeels gnirud gidnihs a dloh ot esoohc uoy erofeb secneuqesnoc eht tuoba kniht ,emit txeN
.srekooh gninniw yrettol ot gnitekram erew yeht taht erus saw ehs erom eht ,ereht hguorht deklaw ehs erom eht taht dias neraK
,flow yerg suoucav nwonk tsal eht
.edisni deppets eh nehw klawedis yluJ ynnus a no elddup a ekil detaropave ecnedifnoc sih ,revewoH
dluoW"   ".yadsruhT txen niaga sknird teg ot ekil uoy dluow woh"
serots eht no syalpsid tnagavartxe eht gnisurep sreppohs krow-retfa fo aes gnilior
,tacbob hsiyobmot a
".pihsdneirf fo
.anacrA ro ,raW fo sgoD
nepo ti worht ot dedeen eh fi dekcolnu saw wodniw ehT
.yawyna reh rof ereht neeb yllaer reven d'eH
.rethgil hcum tlef eh
.neht ,tif tsomla dluow tius sih ebyaM
t'nsaw eh taht dezilaer eh ,htnom a retfA
"!etaremolgnoc gnikcuf rallod noillim-itlum eht tsoc dluow ti stnec tahw tsuj ,si melborp ym tahw erac t'nseod eH
.eromyna niart eht no tis ot erehw tuoba suoitneicsnoc neve
,sretnec gnippohs dna sllam evissam fo segde eht ffo gniwolg gnuh sngis noen
.flow a eb ot dedeen eH
"?sriatspu bulc tehcorc eht sI"
.rood eht demmals eh ,tnemtrapa sih ot kcab tog eh nehW
,neht no oG  .taht tuoba yrros m'I
.yhw wonk t'ndid flow ehT
,taeh htiw dehsulf elzzum dna srae s'flow ehT
.yrots hcae rof dnuorgkcab a sa gnivres spihsnoitaler fo bew detcennocretni
,ylsuovren gnippilf srae
.kcab dekohc lladnaR ",haeY"
.tehcorc tuoba yllautca t'nsaw
"?saw eman ruoy dias uoy tahw s'tahT  ?thgir ,lladnaR - uoy tuoba
.ffo deliart lladnaR ".wonk uoy ,lleW
ot gniklat saw eh erugif eht fo elzzum sselepahs eht no krims eht dna
.ylerusiel erom dewollof esle enoyreve dna taes reh fo tuo thgir deppoh haraS
,saw llib eht taf woh was eh nehw
"?gnikaeps dehsinif uoy erA" ,dias yhtomiT erofeb ecnelis fo sdnoces wef a erew erehT
.enog saw ti neht dna
.yzarc os gnihtemos yrt flow eht ees ot gnitteg susrev yenom eht dehgiew ehs ro eh sa
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
hctip sih ni stfihs eht fo seiteltbus eht woh dneherpmoc t'ndluoc yehT
.rellams flesmih ezeeuqs ot deirt eH
.erofeb ta gnikool neeb d'yeht sretnec gnippohs citnagig eht fo ezis eht flah
.pu kaeps ot esohc eh nehw elzzum delkceps ,ybbuts s'haraS no kool eht dna
,mih dedlocs mom siH
.esirprus eht niur ot tnaw t'nod I ,llew
.niht ro kciht ,enoyreve rof elbatrofmocnu ylthgils eb ot hguone ediw tsuj saw taht elbat eht dna
reven dnah derruf nworb ,tfos s'haraS
secap lareves drawrof deppets dna
!dnatsrednu t'ndluow eh tuB"
,ylsuoiruf knilb mih gnikam seye s'flow eht denetaerht sraeT
nekciuq ot nageb efil yliad fo ytilanab gnigdurd ehT
.detcartxe neeb dah ydob reh erehw ssarg eht no tuo noitacol eht gnilcric
.mih ot esolc pu deldduc saw esle enoemos ekil leef mih edam taht
.gniddorp dna gnikop eht gniod haraS lla saw ti ,emit sihT
.egelloc dna loohcs hgih ni kcab sdneirf evah ot desu eH
.esuap tnatiseh a retfa deksa haraS
eht htiw flesmih dnuorrus ot nosaer dilav a pu deparcs tsal lladnaR ecnis sraey neeb dah tI
.tcefrep saw bulc tehcorc ehT
yrassecen saw naht ecaps erom on htiw niht dna gnol saw moor ehT
,feiler sih ot hcuM
.tnemtrapa ytic ynit eht ni eganam dluoc eh spets evif eht htrof dna kcab decap lladnaR
niap dna raef htiw maws daeh sih elihw
".ecin eb dluow yadsruhT  .uoy rof dooG  .hO"
ni kcab daeh sih dekcud ylhsipeehs lladnaR
.roolf dnuorg eht no ecaps a droffa ot hguone yhtlaew
”enoL“:yojne esaelP
.sllih tpmeknu revo
.flesmih etipsed deddon eh tub
.setteragic esool dna ,srepparw ydnac
.ecnatpecca dna yrevocsid fo yrots sih evow
.thgir saw ehs ebyaM
,dliw eht ni tuo sevlow yerg suoucav fo sngis yna rof hcraes eht no neeb evah stsitneicS"
.yks eht ni wol gnignah noom a fo revils eht dna
;revo saw pihsnoitaler ehT
,delgnat eht gniwonk tuohtiw
,rettum dehsuh a ni deksa dna reh dehcaorppa lladnaR
.ecnavda eht evah yam uoY  .llew yreV"
,eninac neve meht fo enon
srats tniaf eht ta pu dna tuo dekool eH
.ti pleh t'ndluoc I"
>>>><<<<       .nwo sih htiw yletanoissap dekcol
.lla si tahT"   "-I tuB"
.ecnelis otni kcab llef moor ehT
.noitasrevnoc htiw efil ot kcab dezzub ylwols moor eht
,em esucxe - gnirednow saw I"
.ytic gnillems-rat dna -enilosag ytrid yna naht erom yhtlaeh dna gnorts mih peek dluow mraf eht taht
deirc ehs dna
"?trats annog s'ohw ,oS"
,aera eht ni sgnitsil eht desworb eh daetsnI
skcap wen ekam ot yawa derednaw lla d'yehT
".won syadirF no gnihtemos tog ev'I"
.lwoh eht fo egaugnal eht dootsrednu sdneirf wen sih fo enoN
etomer eht no rewop eht tih flow ehT
.yawa dellup neeb dah teknalb a ekil tlef tI
,mraf eht evael ot ton mih dlot syawla namow flow ylrub ehT
.niart eht no tas eh nehw enola tsom tlef syawla drehpehS lladnaR
,anuY no troper tsal ruo ecniS
.teprac deniats sih revo ssecxe eht lla gnirettil
.neraK dna haraS neewteb dehsums ,llaw kcab eht gnola pu dedne lladnaR
.esuom desserd ylprahs eht htiw pihsnoitaler fo dnik taht dah enoyna detbuod eh ,esruoc fO
sih revo dils wap s'eod ehT
ruf sih rednu htmraw gniwolg a delbbub edirp fo egrus A
'.slrig gnikrow' ot reh detcerroc xof citcra eht morf lwocs A
,ssob sih etah t'ndid lladnaR
mra reppu s'lladnaR revo cirbaf tuat eht tsniaga desserp looW
,sdik deretsof ,deirram dah enoyrevE
.hcum os uoy knahT"
tahW"   .sgninrom eht ni sgge dna tsaot rieht dekil yeht woh neve ro ,ot krow ot cisum etirovaf rieht
.ni tif d'eh taht kniht t'ndid eh
?dloh spup uoy lla seitrap dliw esoht fo eno tsoh uoy retfa liat ruoy evas ot em rof hsiw uoy dnA"
,flesmih deidaets
,ssengnihton ot kcab dedaf gnos sih sA
,elihw a ni ecno yreve segassem degnahcxe kcap dlo siH
"?flesym nialpxe ot tnemom a em evig esaelp uoy dluoW
denoihsuc eht tif ot
.sesiar ro sesunob ot noitacolla rof tneserp eb regnol on dluow taht
.snoitasrevnoc dehsuh ni
.wonk ton od I ,oN"
.eralg htaed a htiw moor eht tpews haraS tub ,derekcins nemow lareveS  ".delwoh I"
.elpoep rehto htiw od dluoc eh taht gnihtemos t'nsaw taht tub ,sebuc s'kibuR ta doog yllaer gnitteg emit fo tol a tneps eh egelloc ni kcaB
,gnidliub tauqs a fo tnemesab eht otni gnidael sriats fo thgilf a nwod derutseg dna deppots haraS
?doog os tlef gnilwoh nehw sevlesmeht niartser seninac dluow yhW
,wap ni puc yawriats worran eht dednecsa eH
.ezeerb eltneg eht otni dna
.ytpme ylraen saw niart eht tsael tA
.mraf eht no buc gnuoy a saw eh ecnis delwoh t'ndah eH
.skcolb laicremmoc erom htiw deltsub ytic eht erehw
sresserd dna sebordraw gnihctam-non lareves erehw ,segde eht ot tuo devohs neeb dah selbaT
eluY sih ot anuY eht fo spil eht dna
sgnul sih fo tuo deruop ,efil fo ytilanab dna ssenilenol eht ,noitome pu tnep eht llA
fo xim a htiw mih ta dekool moor eht ni nemow eht
.denettalf srae sih dna
,swap sih morf daeh sih desiar eh sA
dias ehs ",ti yrt uoy llit' ti kconk t'noD"   .desufnoc ,deksa lladnaR "?ekoaraK"   .srettel ybur tnecseroulf ni "ekoaraK teerts dr35" dewolg evoba ngis ehT
.esirprus 'srebmem eht dehpargoerohc moor eht dnuora sliat dna srae fo elggaw A  .deunitnoc ehs
.ecnelis ni denword tnemtrapa sih dna
?gniklat saw eh elihw retupmoc sih morf pu dekool neve yhtomiT daH
!ruf esuom ni tobor a ekil s'eH
.moor llams eht fo ria yffuts eht ni gnuh lwoh xuaf reh sa dezeeuqs dna
.ecivda doog ekil dednuos detseggus d'eh tahw taht dias dna deddon
rehto hcae ot gnihgual ro spal rieht ni sngised lufroloc detehcorc yeht sa no gnihctaw yldesuma rehtie saw esle enoyrevE
.eef eht yap ot piks ot evah ot gniog saw eh slaem hcihw nalp yllatnem ot nageb eh ,noitats niart eht ot deklaw eh sA
,eluY tuoba gniklat erew yehT
,9 emulov GNAF seigolohtna eht ni seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,sevloW :seicepS
.ecnavda na teg ebyam dluoc I elbissop erew ti fi taht gnipoh saw I
.serots tfarc ot spohs ybboh ot seirecorg morf gnihtyreve gnisitrevda
.ruf sih ssorca srevihs tnes dna
,terces lacitirc a gnitcetorp erew eh fi sa
.os od ot deganam enon tub ,pot eht ot esir ot rehtona eno revo derebmalc dna thguof secioV
".ytivitcudorp ruo tcapmi ylereves dluow revognah A
,daed saw moM dnA
.retupmoc sih morf pu kool neve t'ndid esuom ehT  .detrats eh ",riS"
,flesti no denrut hcamots siH
"!ni no thgir emoC  !ereht dnats tsuj t'noD"
,pal reh no skcos eot-fooh dettink-flah dna seldeen tehcorc reh gnivaeL
.yks eht hguorht gnittuc eton ylno eht saw sih tuB
sriahc fo elcric eht ni staes ytpme lareves eht fo hcihw wonk t'ndid eh taht gnizilaer erofeb
sdneirf wen sih llet ot gniog saw eh seirots eht htiw deipucco syawla dnim sih dnuof lladnaR sa
,niaga ti kcol ot ydaer
.rehtie eiredaramac esolc a t'nsaw ti tub
.shtailoG munimula dna ssalg owt neewteb guns deltsen
.tnemssarrabme ni wol gnuh srae dna sliaT
.moor nedoow esraps a ni elcric a ni gnittis nemow fo hcnub a fo detsisnoc bulc tehcorc ehT
,ecaps hguone ylniatrec saw ereht hguoht nevE
"?flow yletats ,emosdnah siht fo efil eht ni gnineppah s'tahW"
.kcab meht thgif ot gniliaf dna gniyrt
,denruter gnileef ehT
.snoitaicossa flow lacol rof tenretni eht dehcraes eh
ydob sih hguorht dehsur dah taht ssendliw eht dekil eH  .t'ndid eh tub
.trebmemac fo leehw a tsniaga efink eseehc a ekil sevren s'lladnaR hguorht decils eciov yllasan s'esuom ehT
,rettOtnacifingiS yb ”enoL“
.stfut tpmeknu esiwrehto eht htiw gniglub morf taoc tius llams oot sezis owt eht peek ot trohs demmirt-dnah
,revewoh ,sgnineve yadirF fo eltsub emoh-gniog eht gniruD
.niaga gnilims ylneddus saw haraS
.edir niart dim gniraehs peehs a ffo llup yllautca dluoc eh taht ecnedifnoc on dah lladnaR
.sedir niart sih fo noitalosi eht ot
detsetorp lladnaR
O na otni delruc elzzum s'lladnaR fo pit ehT
",ekil d'uoy fi em ot txen tis nac uoY"
mih dehsuhs tsuj reed eht tub
level reh ot nwod kcab elzzum sih dellup dnah tfos s'haraS
!oowA" fo seirc gnigaruocne dna stuohs lufyalp eht dimA
mih edisni deliob dna delbbub erif ehT
.dnim sih tuo nword ot noisivelet eht no denrut eH
.flow wen a saw eh ekil tlef lladnaR
.dereffo ylippah ehs
,mih ot txen tas dna ni emac haraS nehW
,yad txen eht emitrevo devorppanu-llits fo sruoh owt sih fo tsrif eht roF
,reh rof erusolcne sih decap eH
"?yako uoy era ,yeH"
.detcejretni ,xof citcra derepmap llew dna pu deffulf a
.ecivda lufpleh fo stib ro snoitseuq htiw yllanoisacco detcejretni dna gnola deddon dna denetsil yehT
.gninnips saw gnihtoN
"- yas dna mih ot pu og ot gniog tsuj er'uoY"
.detaes saw enoyreve retfa elkcuhc suovren a htiw dias lladnaR
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
ygolohtna eht ni dehsilbup tsrif saw yrots sihT .srettO
.detnarraw eh taht deveileb eh naht ecnedifnoc erom hcum htiw
.lausu sa gnol sa eciwt leef ot etummoc sih tuo gniggard
.yletaidemmi eciton d'eh ,sruf elkna s'flow eht fo elgnis a fo pit eht revo dehsurb ssarg fo edalb a fI
.s'eninac a sa egde gnicreip emas eht ro hctip thgir eht evah t'ndid tI
detsiwt hcamots siH
.spuorg ybboh ot no devom lladnaR
pu gniytterp retfA
gnitaes detnuom llaw
,kcen dna tsehc sih revo ruf eht deltsur hgis gnivaeh A
tnemtrapa sih raen skcolb gnisuoh detsissa tnemnrevog eht hguorht thgin ta enola gniklaw deracs ssel saw lladnaR
,remmus otni demossolb gnirps sA
noitutitser ni srallod derdnuh owt droldnal eht dewo eh taht dias rood sih ot depat eciton a ,yad txen ehT
dluoc eh tseb sa gnola dewollof dna delims flow ehT
.gnos eht htiw hguorht dehsup eh tub
"?enoemos teem uoy did - uoy diD
.dluoc eh taht aedi eht dehsiler eh tub
.ecnedifnoc lausu reh
.aedi tihs a neeb dah egelloC
.nioj ot gniksa dna
.ot derutseg ehs taes eht ni flesmih tas dna deddon lladnaR
htiw
.desolc ti dils dna
,bulc tehcorc eht fo nemow eht ,eno yb enO
.ytrap a t'nsaw ti tub ,diputs gnihtemos did I ,naem I - evah yam I"
.sih tfel
.hcniw a ni thguac saw ti ekil dehcnelc tsehc sih dna daeh sih dedoolf snoitome dna sthguoht lacisnesnoN
,aidyL  "!das os saw tahT
.sraey ni meht fo yna ot nekops t'ndah eh dna
,dekrow eh erehw gnidliub eciffo gnirewot eht morf skcolb wef a ylno saw bulc eht ,retteb nevE
:seicepS ygolohtna eht fo rotide
,anuY etam sih gninioj si eh taht gniwonk ysae tser nac ew tub ,erus rof ydegart a si tI
"!emit a ta enO  !hsuhS"
".krow ruoy ot nruter esaelP
,nepo ti deppilf dna tuo ti erot eH
.sgnul dna tsehc sih denethgit erusserp dna
.nwod deteiuq enoyrevE
.seivom noitca ni srekib yalp ot desu taht sdnik eht
.delruc elzzum reed gnol s'haraS fo segde ehT  ".klat
"?ereh uoy thguorb tahw su llet uoy t'nod yhw ,yeH
puorg eht gnitnorfnoc fo noitautis gniyfirret eht otni flesmih gniworht erofeb gnidliub eht htiw elbatrofmoc eb ot tnatropmi saw tI
.noitalosi nwo sih ni gnilever tsuj naht esrow ylbacilpxeni saw
,esu d'eh sdrow eht enigami ot dekil eh ,os nevE
,tnemom a retfa ,revewoH
,rettOtnacifingiS yb ”enoL“ saw sihT
,tbuod hsipeehs fo tnemom a retfa ,flow eht hcihw guh a dereffo neht dna
.ylsuoires mih koot enoyreve ,detrats eh nehw srekcins eht etipseD
ria thgin detnecs-tsuahxe yllihc eht ni tel dna esor tI
.erofeb emitefil sih ni dah eh naht
,emit tsal ekil tcejretni t'ndid esuom ehT
".daeha oG  .yam uoY"
.daerd saw tcnitsni tsrif siH
.klat ll'eh ,klat ot stnaw eh fI  !neraK ,ti tuhs hO"
,gniliec eht sdrawot elzzum sih detlit eH
,hctal eht revo gnuh wap siH
.daeh sih revo thgiarts welf ruoh swen eht fo tsoM
.esuom gnipyt ylsuoiruf eht ta nwod dekool eh sa ekahs ot ton tseb yrev sih did lladnaR
,dias lladnaR ",miT yeH"
.dezilaer ti erofeb ffo loow s'peehs a flah rossics ot elba gnieb no kcehcyap a teb evah dluow lladnaR
.redluohs s'haraS eltsur ot mih dnuora dehcaer neraK
?skcap rieht htiw delwoh yeht nehw ekil tlef sevlow suoucav tahw siht saW     .efil ytic fo
sredluohs sih dnuora srevoc ruf xuaf htiw
.nwo rieht tuoba gnitsaob yltbus dna sevil s'rehto hcae no pu gnikcehc
.tsehc sih ni gninrub peed a
.ecaps lanosrep ruoy dedavni yeht nehw tnih eht tog reven peehS
.detatsaved saw eluY ,gnissap s'anuY retfA"
,ediw mih ta delims retnuoc eht ta lrig tibbar ehT
,rebmemer neve t'ndid eh yadhtrib esohw rehtorb a ot degnoleb mraf eht ,daed saw daD
.gnihtemos redro ot ton etilopmi ylbaborp saw ti taht dezilaer neht dna
,sevlow suoucav eht ni was eh taht flesmih fo elttil a saw ereht taht meht dlot yltnatiseh eH
"!ereh s'lladnaR ,yeH"  .mih deciton
".niaga neppah t'now ti taht esimorp I
.retupmoc a no srebmun ta gnirats syad gnol retfa kcits ot demees reven tI
.rebmemer t'ndluoc lladnaR
?yadseuT no deneppah tahW"
.eluY sih rof anuY a dedeen eH
,llaw raf eht tseraen riahc eht fo kcab eht dehcuot ylraen ti taht peets os ,foor eht
.klat ot detrats enoyreve ,taht tA
.mih morf detnaw ydob sih tahw dezilaer eh
.eno eno enin desserp sdap gnikahS
.elpoep rehto neewteb syawla erew staes nepo wef ylno eht
.lwoh laer a ekil dnuos t'ndid tuohs reH    "!oooowA" tuo
.margorp eht fo dne eht dekrep srae sih ,revewoH
.seninac tneipas dnuora gnitanigiro tsom
depoord liat s'flow ehT