.nehctik eht morf eciov s’rehtaf sih draeh eh sa derevihs eH
----**----  …mih dnuora depparw smra eht tuoba kniht ot ton deirt eh dna
”.tuoba yrrow ot ytinummi tog ew
,esnet saw dnah sih tub ,deppots dah eh nehw wonk t’ndid eH
.anatnoM ni kcab srobhgien sih
,siht ekil emag a ni ,lleW“
,kaeps ot htuom sih denepo yrevA
,drah dna railimaf ecno ta saw ydob sih fo edis thgir eht htaeneb retlehs ehT
,gnihtyreve no gnuh tI
,dnuorg eht otni dradnats s’ebirt rieht detnalp ehs sa lehcaR ta dekool yrevA
.erif eht otni yltcerid dekool neht eH
,erehwemos ,enoemos
,srats eht ot kcab daeh sih denrut yrevA
.segap ytiniffAruF sih ro
;ecalp railimafnu
,mih dniheb tfihs a tlef eh neht saw tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,delkcuhc nauQeD ”.yb desirprus eb ot ecin gnihtemos s’ereht sseug I…tuB“
,hO“  kcezzoW .A yrraH yb
,emag taorhttuc yrev a saw ti taht thgir saw atreboR
.ni klaw ebirt omamahaM eht dehctaw yeht neht saw tI
”.pleh ot nwod m’I
s’tI“ .teef ’semaJ yb gab palrub eht deciton yrevA nehT ”.ees ll’eW“
yraw…erom eb lla d’uoy thguoht I“
,teef sih ffo mih llup gnihtemos tlef yrevA ,ylnedduS ”!ti welb
.srehtaef sih neve ,gnihtyreve detnit egnaro fo edahs suonimo nA
,htimS .srM a osla saw ehS
.meht no sgniward kni edurc htiw srepap fo wels a gnoma knas eH
”!timmad ,emitemos niw ot tnaw tsuj I !skcus tI“
.drawrof dehcoocs haeL ,gnihtyna yas dluoc raguoC eht erofeb tub ,denworf atreboR
.tcaer dluow lluB tiP eht woh gniees ,yllatnemirepxe
ekil eb t’nac ti ,tsael tA“ .rehsiF .srM dias
.deknilb yrevA .onihR eht deksa
”.og annog s’taht woh wonk lla ew ,’niretnilps secnailla htiW“ .dias ehs
knas ylwols eh sa
.yltneg gnikcilf srae s’raguoC eht ,deddon atreboR
.nauQeD sdrawot ylthgils denrut yrevA
seye sih denepo kwaH ehT
,democlew eh ssenegnarts a ,revewoh ,saw tI
.tniop doog a pu gnirb ay sseug I“ .dehgis atreboR
.rehtegot sretnuH regnevacS revo
.mih dniheb gnihsiws liat sih ,deddon neht dna ,sebirt htob dedrager eH
.yawa gnillup ton tub erutsop sih gnitsujda ,dehgis eH
.decaf eh ssenkcalb eht ot tsartnoc ni eulb yvan saw mih dniheb yks ehT
.godpeehS eht ot revo dessorc neht drehpehS namreG ehT ”.tcefrep s’tI“
,mih ot dnik tub gnihton neeb dah lluB tiP ehT
.hcteks ot deunitnoc eh os
.yletaidemmi tsomla dedaf ti ,elims s’nauQeD fo thgis eht ta tub ,niaga esor noisnet suovren siH
.daeh sih fo pot eht delkcit sehcnarb eht yaw eht leef tsomla dluoc eh dna
enoemos evas ot su ’niksa
.maerd a morf pu nekow tsuj dah eh fi derednow yrevA dna
~~~~**~~~~ .rebmuls peed a otni
,dennirg lehcaR ”!teb uoY“ ”?lehcaR
.derepsihw nauQeD ”?wol taht srebmun htiw egnellahc eht od ot elba eb llits ll’yeht kniht aY“
,ruoh sih dedne dah nosrednA rekcuB fi nevE
”.siht no tnemgduj ruoy tsurt ll’I“
”,omamahaM ,uoy rof syad net hguot ytterp a neeb
.ecnedac lacisum a gniyrrac eciov reh
.redluohs s’iaM gnigdun yltneg
tnemom taht ta spets eht pu gnidnuob rehtaf sih denigami eH
”.thgin fo emit siht ta ylevol era sratS“
VT no ti dehctaw yeht fi tcaer dluow rehtaf sih woh wenk eh
.dedeen yrevA lla saw taht tub ,pih sih no swap s’nauQeD fo tcatnoc thgil a tlef ylno yrevA
.deunitnoc rehtaf s’yrevA
”?wonk uoy ynA“ .nauQeD deksa ”?haeY“
.wor tnorf eht ta doots eh erehw morf daeh sih gnikahs elonA eht ,ylrettib delkcuhc elyK
”?htimS .srM ot taht wohs dluohs I kniht aY“
.nihtiw yal taht tra eht tuoba gnikniht
.dnuorg eht otni gnihsarc diova ot ylsselesu deppalf smra sih sa maercs a tuo tel kwaH ehT ”!nac uoy ,seY“
,thgir ,oot ti htiw gnola gniog er’uoy teb I“
.ereht ni saw tahw rof gnikool dna
.ylsuoicsnocbus ti otni denael yrevA dna
”,egatnavda taht deen neve ll’ew kniht t’nod I
,epacsdnal eht ssorca lerrab
,evah syawla yeht sa ylroop sa seod omamahaM dna tniop taht ot steg ti fI“ .dias eh
”.taorhttuc steg emag eht nehw rof ydaer eb annaw tsuj I
,ksed sih ni reward a ta decnalg eH
”.nur gnol eht ni uoy pleh thgim ti taht ecnahc-ffo eht ni ti ot eerga ot esnes erom ekam d’ti kniht I“ .eeL dias
.daeh sih fo kcab eht debbur eh sa etunim a elim a decar sthguoht s’kwaH ehT
.delahxe nauQeD .dehgis eH
ylthgils eht fo ytitnedi eht saw dnoces ehT
.gnieb eritne sih hguorht doolf feiler fo esnes a tlef eh sa daeh sih gniwob
,etipser feirb a saw tI
,mih erofeb doots llits rehtaf siH
,ualaP ni did yeht ekil ebirt rehto eht no noitautis ton-evah a dellup yeht sselnu tub
,tey dna ,won yb naibsel a neeb adluohs I
”!lamron ton si tahT“
”,em tuoba wonk ot elpoep emos tnaw t’nod I sgniht…era erehT“
”.emag ym rof doog t’nia ay rof rebmun rehtona tub
”,od uoy tahw rettam on emag eht ni etal taht retnilps lliw secnailla esohT“
,dias dna redluohs s’atreboR no fooh a decalp aralC
”,sneppah ti ecno ,egrem eht rof era snalp ruoy tahW“
…nauQeD eguag ot emit a reve saw ereht fI
saw tI .tuo gnihcteks saw eh egap cimoc eht fo enil eulb eht tuo ekam ot mih rof
~~~~**~~~~ …snoissucsid thgin-etal
”?taht wonk uoy ,gnitsugsid er’uoY“
.dnuorg eht otno dna retlehs eht fo egde eht tsap dekool eh sa gniralf srehtaef sih
.egap cimoc eht gnihcteks deppots dah dnah gniward sih taht neht ylno gnizilaer ,deknilb yrevA
.yrevA deksa ”?tahw tuobA“
.mih dnuora degnahc dah gnihtyreve dnif ot seye sih denepo yrevA ”.esaelp rof etal elttil a s’tI“
.semaJ ,raf os llew ’niod neeb ev’eW“
.ekatsim a t’nia siht epoh I“
.pih sih fo evruc eht revo gnikans tsuj sregnif eht
”.sseug I ,ti pleh t’nac I
”.ti etaicerppa I“ .derepsihw yrevA
.maerd sih ni gniraeppa erew yeht yhw derednow eh ,meht tuoba thguoht eh sa dna
.stamrof eldniK ro kcabrepap ni rehtie ,nozamA no ti dnif nac uoy
.ylper eht rof gnitiaw
.ria eht ni tuo gnar eciov s’rehtaf siH
”?ebirT omamahaM tsniaga sesseccus egnellahc ruoy pu peek ot ygrene eht evah ll’uoy kniht uoy od ,ebirT ajnaM ni redael a sa ,atreboR“
.esuoh eht revo emac ecnelis A
.rehtie nauQeD tnioppasid ot tnaw t’ndid eh ,dlot eb hturt tub
.anatnoM raen erehwyna morf did ti naht saniloraC eht morf yltcnitsid erom dednuos gnawt sih dna ,evitatirohtua dna peed saw tI
”,ereht ti sekam omamahaM fi srebmun ruo rof doog eb d’tI“ .deggurhs nauQeD ”.ekil
,timda attog uoY“ .atreboR dias
,aedi dab a eb ll’ti ebyam ,eruS
.doots dah htimS .srM erehw drawot devom yrevA ”!siht wonk uoY“
,denworf atreboR ”.elbissop fI .sey-
.ajnaM revo llef ecnelis A
.skcas hsiyerg elpitlum htiw teksab a tuo gnillup ,denrut eh ,siht htiW
.pmac fo egde eht ot resolc gnipeels derreferp eH
”,detcepxenu eht tcepxe
.mraerof sih tsniaga yltneg pu sserp woble s’nauQeD tlef yrevA ,tnemom taht tA
”.maet a gnorts taht tsuj er’ew esuac’ ,meht revo llormaets ll’ew dnA
”,thgir tuoba sdnuoS“
,drawno decar traeh
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
!sffub ruoy pord ,ydobyrevE“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.pmal ksed a rof evas ,krad saw moor siH .dehgis yrevA
nerrab saw dleif ehT
”,omamahaM wen eht ta kool tsrif rieht gnitteg ajnaM“
”!won thgir gniod er’uoy tahw wonk uoY !did uoy tahw wonk uoY“ ”?yhW“
.evitisnes taht erew uoy wonk t’ndiD .yrroS“
:levon detprecxe s’yadot dehsilbup-fles sah eH .kcezzoW rreH sa goD fo ecioV eht ot nwonk esiwrehto
.seert yrrehc eht morf sevael gnikconk
.htimS .srM htiw devil taht namow rehto eht sa yawa thgiarts tsomla godpeehS eht dezingocer yrevA ”…sseug I“ ”!seirrehc emos kcip dna ereht tuo teg s’tel ,no emoC“
.dniw eht ni nwod sserd reh gnidloh
!syaw rieht ot nerdlihc gnitrevnoc eb ll’yeht ,hguone nooS“ ~~~~**~~~~ …sgniht rehto dehctaw eh yaw eht
,deksa rednamalaS eht ”?rettam ti seoD“
,htmraw elbatrofmoc ylegnarts a saw ereht tub ,tsacrevo ylthgils saw yad ehT
~~~~**~~~~ …litnu retsaf dna
.thgilrats eht ni gnitnilg elims hsilived emas taht htiw kwaH eht ta nwod gnikool
”.taht no kcab ym tog ev’uoy kniht I ,won rof tuB“
.yltneg ti no nwod gniraeb nus tsuguA eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
Y“ ”?huh ,ecnailla ruoy ot elyK reets ot tnaw uoy os
,ecafrus redrah hcum a no edis sih no peels netfo dluow eH
”.egnahc nac sgnihT“ .dias eeL
.evoba srats eht fo weiv tseb eht dedivorp tpels eh erehw dna
”,skniht eh tahw ni kcots fo tol a tup ay ekil sdnuoS“
,epacsrats lufituaeb a saw ti
.daeh reh gnikahs godpeehS eht htiw
.nibac a fo edistuo gnidnats drehpehS namreG desserd ylenilucsam rehtar a gniees
.aremac no siht gnitteg saw
;uoy rof etal oot s’ti tuB
.retlehs eht fo egde eht ta thgir
,thgir sih ot denrut yrevA
!edistuo yad ylevol a s’tI !esiuoL“
”.oddik ,onnud I ,lleW“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.era yeht tahw rednow I
.dias reveirteR nedloG eht
,dnuora denrut yletaidemmi yrevA
”,taht ekil ton s’tI“
,kcezzoW .A yrraH yb
.thgirla er’uoY“
,slirtson sih ni decnad seirrehc fo llems ehT
”!ti pleh t’nac I !yrros m’I“
.daeh sih koohs eH ”…ynnhoJ…J“
”!seod yob doog a tahw ton si sihT“
.daeh sih ni tuo gnar eciov s’ynnhoJ
:txen yas dluow semaJ tahw yltcaxe tsomla gniwonk ,dellits eh ,siht deye yrevA sa dnA
.ylwols kwah eht ot denrut eH .dias eeL
”eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL“ morf
tprecxe na si yrots s’yadoT dna
,esrow gnihton enigami dluoc yrevA ,ynnhoJ htiw deneppah dah taht gnihtyreve retfA
,dnah sih no daeh sih depporp nauQeD ”.thgiR“
.dnuora erew swerc aremac eht thgin ta etal woh
”,yhtrowtsurt si elyK“ ”.ekatsim
neht dna ,ees lliw elpoep rehto taht sgniht eseht lla ekam yehT
,emit on detsaw semaJ
,em fo tnorf ni ssik shtimS eht nees ev’I semit fo rebmun eht ekil leef I esuaceb esnes ekam t’nseod tsuj tI
,ereht tas ohw godpeehS redlo
”.egrem eht litnu gnisol peek t’nac yeht
?eh si ,gnorw ton s’eh…tsuj s’tI“
.yrevA dias ”,yllaer toN“
,si sa emag eht otni keew a ylno
.aera gnipeels lanummoc eht ni tops sih no ni delttes yrevA
.erif eht drawot delffuhs eeL
,dias rehtom s’yrevA
uoy dna ,ecnahc ruoy dah uoY“
”.ereht syawla t’nera rof ’nikool er’uoy sgniht
noertaP sih no rehtie sih fo skrow rehto dnif nac uoY
.seert yrrehc eht lla fo
.nauQeD dnif ot kcab dekool eh dna
,seye s’goD eht ni feihcsim emos was eh nrows evah dluoc yrevA .seye s’rehto hcae otni dezag lluB tiP eht dna kwaH ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.deunitnoc godpeehS eht
,retlehs eht fo retnec eht ot resolc tpels yllausu nauQeD ”.evitisnes
.thgil eht ni gnitnilg seye yarg peed sih
,sdneirf yb dednuorrus flesmih dnuof eh ,tnemom taht ta tub
dednob dah dad sih dna yrevA
,peels emos teg dluohs eW“
er’eW“ .dias ehs ”,tniop a sah eH“
”,emag eht ni ylrae s’ti ,niagA“ ”?taht fo
:mih teiuqsid ot hguone saw enola tcaf tahT
.wohs ym si siht dna
,driew s’ti…tsuj tI
.llor eye eht ezilausiv dluoc yrevA ”.od ekam nac uoY“
.gnilbmur dna peed dnuos eht
,neht mih egdelwonkca t’ndid yeht ,yrevA draeh dah yeht fI ”!htimS .srM“
,nosrednA rekcuB ,tsoh ruoy m’I
.mih ot pu gnihsur rehtaf sih fo egasiv eht gniees
.dehsinav dah ti ,esuoh eht ta kcab dekool yrevA nehW ”?….srM ,thgiR
.mraf a no flesmih dnuof yrevA
”,edistuo mraw oot s’tI“
,ereht fo tuo teg ot thguoht eH
.atreboR ot denrut semaJ
:anatnoM ni erew yeht naht esnetni erom erew taht racsagadaM fo srats eht tuoba gnihtemos saw erehT
”…llew-W“ ”.ma I ereh
”.dnim t’nod uoy fi ti otni teg ton rehtar…d’I“
.dias ehs ”,ahcteg I ,haeY“
”.yawyna gnipeels t’nsaw I
.stam labirt lausu rieht otni detros ebirT ajnaM eht ,noitaralced lausu ’semaJ tA ”!syug ,ni no emoC“
tsuj trihs sih fo kcab eht
.ebirt ajnaM eht fo tser eht fo serons eht yb dedaneres ,eton taht ni ti koot yrevA dna
,yrevA ,esneffo oN“ .atreboR dias
.egrem eht dna won neewteb neppah ot gniog s’tahw wonk t’nod ew dna
”!yob doog a eb ot uoy desiar I“
fo eno ekil ,railimaf dekool drehpehS namreG eht taht saw tsrif eht
eciov s’rehtaf sih draeh eh nehw saw tahT ”!uoy erad woH“
.taht od thgim taht elpoep rehto tuoba yrrow attog ew
.esir ot tuoba saw nus eht dna
:sgniht owt dezilaer eh taht no dekool eh sa saw tI
?hO“ .deunitnoc kwaH eht
,kcezzoW .A yrraH yb
”.gnihtyreve tuoba mih ot tnew I .haeY“ .dias eh
.edils ti tel ot saw tcnitsni sih tub
!gnorw gnihtyna gniod ton s’ehS“
”,did uoy fi mraf eht no kcab su tel reven d’ehs wonk uoy ,semaJ ,esaelP“
”!nialpxe em tel tsuJ !esaelp ,ynnhoJ“
.osrot s’nauQeD revo gnitsohg
na ni gnieb fo llaftip a s’taht semitemoS“ .dias eh
”eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL“ fo 5 retpahC saw sihT     ”!sebirt gnippaws er’eW
thgil hguone tsuj saw tI
.naiva eht dniheb morf tuo deklaw loohcs tra ni syad sih morf dezingocer eh onihR a
.kcab taht devresed eh ,mih ot dnik siht eb ot gniog saw nauQeD fI .loohcs tra ni ynnhoJ htiw deneppah tahw fo taeper a tnaw t’ndid eh dna
reeD llat rehtar a fo retceps eht tuo ekam yltniaf dluoc eh ,mih dniheB
?siht gniees ot ekat eh dluow woH
”!del taht erehw si sihT“
:retlehs eht edistuo thgiarts detrad seye siH
.txen emac tahw wenk yrevA
,emag eht ni retal erid steg ti fi tub ,won esimorp nac ew hcum s’ereht kniht t’nod I ,yrevA“
.dap hcteks eht evoba tsuj gnirevoh licnep enileulb eht fo pit eht
yramotsuc ’stnerap sih naht rehto no etartnecnoc ot gnihtemos mih evig ot gnihtyna ,dipar erom
”,oN“ .deksa nauQeD ”?saremac eht fo tnorf ni toN“
kcen sih fo kcab eht fo srehtaef eht no gnicnad htaerb s’nauQeD evah ot saw ti egnarts woh tsuj dezilaer eh gnissentiw erew yeht tahw ekil thgin raelc a no tub
.ylla na rof ’nihtyna ,yeH“
”.tniop a tog ay sseug I“ .dehgis atreboR
”,elyK tuoba kcab ym gnivah rof sknahT“
”.ekatsim a gnikam eb ll’ew kniht t’nod I“ .dias yrevA
”.tpada dna segnahc esoht ta kool nac reyalp trams a kniht I“
”!edahs eht fo tuo emoC
.elyK ot yltcerid denrut eH
.elims sih tuo ekam tsuj dluoc yrevA
lufknaht saw yrevA dna ,kaerb eht revo mih htiw emoh nekat dah eh eno ,sessalc sih fo eno rof tnemngissa trohs a
”.thgin tsal licnuoC labirT ta tuo detov yraM“ .dias reveirteR eht
.ecno rof pmac eht dnuora sthgil aremac yna t’nerew ereht dezilaer eH .yrevA dias
”,tey tsuj su rof egats taht tih t’nsah tI“
”.ereh raen esle erehwyna pu gnipporc taht evah t’nac ew dna
”?hcum siht esol ot leef ti seod woh ,elyK“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.seilla mih esol nac taht dna ,evisarba
.pu dekool yrevA ”!denraw erew uoY“
.pih s’yrevA no gniniamer dnah sih ,erutsop sih detfihs neht eH
…semitemos s’eh wonk I .elttil A“
”.thgin’G“ ”.nauQeD ,thgin’G“ .seye sih
desolc eH .yrevA dias ”,haeY“
”!seirrehc reh tuohtiw eip yrrehc ym ekam t’nac I“
.ereht t’nerew saremac ehT
gnirednow yrevA tfel ti hguohtla
.spih sih no sdnah sih decalp semaJ
”.taht ekil sdnim rieht segnahc ti ylneddus ,moob
osrot s’nauQeD tsniaga
,gnihtyna yas dluoc eh erofeb tub
”.esirprus a evah ew ,yadot dnA“ .dias eh
kcab sih desserp yltbus os reve eh tub
.thgir er’uoy sseug I…“
.osrot sih dnuora depparw smra s’nauQeD dnuof dna ydob sih detfihs eH
.ssengnihton hguorht delbmut eh nwod dna
,ylthgils kcab osrot sih denael yrevA ”.haeY“ ”?gnihtyrevE“
”!esaelp ,daD“ .smra sih gnitfil ,tuhs seye sih dezeeuqs yrevA
.meht dedrager eh sa trihs denori yltnellecxe sih revo smra sih gnissorc
.sretnuH regnevacS ekil emag a ni ytiradilos evah ot saw ti gnitrofmoc ylddo woh gnizilaer ,dnuora decnalg yrevA
”.ni gninut rof uoy knahT
;rehtie ,yssem erew senil eht taht esnes eht ni tra edurc tsuj t’nsaw tI
.evah reven dluoc eh tahw htiw mih detnuat tsomla yrevA ta werht egap hcae secnalg evitseggus eht
.smra reh dessorc atreboR
,spih s’yrevA otni yltneg gud sdapwap s’nauQeD ”.meht
sih sa taht no etartnecnoc ot deirt eh dna
,racsagadaM ni kcab saw eH .yliraelb
.noitcartsid eht rof
.llew ezeerb remmus eht detnemilpmoc taht eno
.lehcaR ot denrut neht ehS .haeL dias ”,emaS“
.etispmac eht ta kcab dnuorg eht ot secnalg suovren s’kwah eht dedrager ehs sa smra reh gnissorc
,ti evah dluow yeht tlef eh ,deneppah revetahw tuB .gniog peek ot meht no eb dluow erusserp eht tlef eh ,stleb rieht rednu wor a ni niw egnellahc htxis rieht htiW
”?ereht ti ekam ll’eh suovren uoY
.meht fo yna ezingocer t’nod I .ereh driew era snoitalletsnoC“
,mih dniheb gnirevoh reeD eht fo retceps eht naht rehtar tub
”.atreboR ,ytironim eht ni er’uoy snaem taht ,alegnA gnitnuoC“
emag eht otni gniog ygrene suovren sih fo lla
,delims eh ,ffo detfird yrevA sA
,ylthgils derevihs eH
.llat gnidnats llits ajnaM fo srebmem lla
,saw ti ereht tub ,dnuorg eht fo tuo gnurps dah nibac eht nehw wonk t’ndid yrevA
retsaf llef eh tub ,nwod wols ot deirt eH
”.egrem ew ecno htiw pu peek t’nac ew ecnailla na rof ’niksa adnik si ay rof omamahaM morf
htaerb hcae htiw gnihsinav
.sretaeht ni tuo gnimoc eivom siht evah t’nac ew yhw si ,sdneirf ym ,taht dnA
”eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL“   yojne esaelP
----**----  .mih rof hguone doog saw taht dna
”,seod adnik tI“ .deknilb atreboR
?wonk uoy ,kciuq os toN .taht
.yrevA drawot demrots eh sa kwaH redlo eht revo derevoh hcihw
.detuohs yrevA ”!tiaw ,daD“
.yrevA ot kcab denrut ehS
,remrif emaceb sekorts siH
.hctiwt mra sih tlef yrevA
,thgilrats eht nI
,dias yrevA ”,uoy knahT“
.ekil kool lliw srebmun rieht tahw wonk t’nod eW“ .aralC dias ”,eurT“