wenk neht pup eht ,werg ti sa oS
;dnuora ecnarp dluow srats sA hgih gnignah saw ecno ytuaeb ehT
,dlihc a tsuj rof dliw oot efil sihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT no
,llirht a efil edam ,flow a ,mrof siH
llits secnartne llirht a tahw dnA
!yob a eb ot emit tahW – delwoh yleelg tub ,delworg regnol oN
;yoj ni dnuora decnad eH
;kcatta na ekil ekirts oT ,yks eht tuo morf
,murtceps msitua eht no
;yks yrrats eht htaeneB llih a nopu tser sih koot eH
.ecaep ni tser dluoc flow ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.raeb ot hcum oot s'efil nehW sees eh tahw era seiromem tuB
.htrim ni yalp ton dluoc eH
enola lla dna ,hsrah saw htuoy siH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
;esaec gnillaf sti morf dnA ,ylf dluow noom eht – won detsuahxE
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
?thgieh ta nees saw tahw nahT
nwonk evah eno dluoc espmilg retteb tahW
.dnuorg eht hsams ot noos saW
,yrruFoS ,ytiniffAruF no
,xuaebroCtnecniV-lehciM yb
.noom gniwolg eht dleheB
;riapsed ni derednaw eH
llef ti neht dnA
noitcelloc yrteop tsrif sih
,dnik os eno a dnif ot drah s'tI
.hgih no elbahcaernU ,thgirb dna lluf saw thgin taht noom ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ikahK yb daeR  .trAtnaiveD ro
xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb meop a ,”nooM ehT & uoraG-puoL“   yojne esaelP
;emit eht ta regnorts dnA
,xuaebroC tnecniV-lehciM yb
lliw s'erutan hguorht no gnidloh tuB
;htrae eht ot gnillup yB
.esrow saw efil namuh siH
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,yrteop ciryl fo rohtua emit-gnol a si ohw
,tsal ta raen werd noom eht nehw dnA
erehps revlis taht ,raen gnisolc tuB
hsilbup-fles ot noos si dna
– nworg si flow eht ,ecneh sega woN
;esruc a demees osla tuB
!thgin ta pu gnikool nO
.kcab thgir noom eht hsup oT htgnel ta deraperp – htgnerts repus htiW – kcal ton did ohw pup ehT
.emilbus tra na sdaerps ohW
.kcab ti gnulf eh litnU
,dum eht otni duht a htiw oS
tsaf gniworg saw noom eht llits tuB
htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
pu gnidloh saw pup elttil tahT
,reehc ot devloseR
yrteop sih fo erom dnif nac uoY ."emulP ehT morF"
– pu gnikool nehw – pup sselyoj tahT noos dna
,tsap gnittegrof ,eguh os noom htiW
”nooM ehT & uoraG-puoL“ saw sihT