.ereh fo tuo ti ekam lliw I ,uoy esimorp I
yrots a em llet yltneitap d’uoy os ,ylsuoivbo ,t’ndluow I dnA .erus m’I ,os-dna-os tnias fo elbarap eht wenk I fi em ksa d’uoy
.elims tub pleh t’nac I ”.ylsuoivbo
,okarA ym ,erofeb yrots taht em dlot dah uoy ebyaM
,uoy llet dluow I ”,yrots ylevol A“
.nrecnoc ni deworruf worb
ylno ecaep rof deyarp I taht gnorw ti sI
.nac I sa tseb sa dnah ruoy ezeeuqs I
.syad wef tsap eht morf sgol ym htiw emit siht
.liat ym no dednal I erehw esiurb thgils a ebyam tpecxe
.yad ym nethgirb llits uoy dna yawa sraey thgil derdnuh a nevE
.alaK ,em ot kcab emoc uoy erus ekaM“
.elbareffusni eb nac uoy noitanigami ym ni neve tub ,efiw lufituaeb ym ,uoy evol I
.yaw gnirussaer ylgnisirprus
.tuo derugif ydaerla ev’uoy tahw ezilaer ot em rof gnitiaw er’uoy nehw teg uoy krims gnitairufni taht
.syad wef tsap eht rof depmac neeb ev’I hcihw edisgnola retarc worran eht
.eerf ti llup ot troffe emos sekat tI
.ten eht ni ecaps eht ni llif ot sehtolc dna sgar dlo ’srobhgien rieht gnisu
,siht dnif uoy nehw em htiw suoiruf eb lliw uoy wonk I“
.dnah ym ekat uoy dna uoy ot tuo hcaer I
,erew ti fi neve dna
.ti ees ot ereh neeb dah uoy hsiw I
,hsifles em sekam taht esoppus I
?gnihtemos no desucof er’uoy nehw eson ruoy fo egdirb eht ta rehtegot pu hcnub sworbeye ruoy yaw eht evol I taht uoy dlot reve I evaH
.snoitar wef tsal eht tae I ,em htiw ti gniluah fo daetsnI .gnihtyreve
.elbide er’yeht
,daeh ruoy tlit uoY
,nommocnu ton s’taht
?mra wen ym otni tliub dah yeht stnemecnahne dna sedargpu suoirav eht fo lla uoy ot denialpxe I nehw ,ti llac uoy did tahW
,raw eht rebmemer uoy oD
.uoy tuoba kniht I ,daetsnI
.ti detneverp evah dluoc I ebyam ,rekciuq riah a neeb tsuj dah I fi tub
.dezilaer ev’uoy tahw ezilaer I nehw yas I ”,hO“
.lluh ruo ni eloh gnipag a
,snotsip eht neewteb gnihtemos si erehT
dedrocer snoisnetxe lausiv ym tahw ees ot kcehc I
,selohtrop eht fo hcae dnuora muinatit fo eceip depahs-enoc a s’ereht ,scitamehcs eht ot gnidroccA
.srevol neve fo taht dnoyeb ssenesolc a seilpmi noisnelced eht tub
su fo reittiw eht syawla erew uoy ,taht naht reittiw—
,pleh rof gniksa egassem trohs a drocer I ,thgin eht rof ni nrut I erofeB
,anlu dna suidar cillatem eht neewteb ecaps eht ni delaes ylluferac
esoht‘ ,yas dna su ta kool eno ekat
.eerf enoc eht sees
.gnibbos dna gnihgual neewteb gnitanretla
,emit eht ta ,uoy llet ot dewolla reven saw I—uoy dlot reven I
.em llet dluow uoy
,su fo suoreneg yrev si hcihw ,htiaf dab ni deksa ton si siht gnimussA
.gniht eht eriwer dna egamad eht riaper ot ,diulf ciluardyh tsol eht ecalper ot pohskrow lluf a deen dluow I
.eye na fo knilb eht ni
”,psarG ruo nihtiW snevaeH ehT“ ni noos dna
em ot trapmi ot gniyrt er’uoy tahw ezilaer I dnA
,noil eht llet uoy ”,hswaC ,ev hkarriM“
pu kaerb rethgierf detner eht ees ,selohtrop eht fo eno hguorht ,dna pihs eht morf yawa hcnual I
.yaw eht fo tuo ylluferac dna senob eht htiw gnitovip
.desufnoc er’uoy nehw elbaroda er’uoY
.thgil egnaro nedlog ni dehtab si dnal
.edisni scinortcele eht ta teg dna revoc rellortnoc eht pop ot rettam laivirt a si ti ,lootitlum eht htiW
.kcap yrettab eht noitnem ot ton
.kniht I ,hguone gnol pu gnitteg
,yhpargoeg dna ygoloeg
.denigami evah I uoy eht ksa I
strap esoht esu nac uoy ,reviecer eht ecifircas uoy fI“
,etihw si gnihtyrevE
.ssenthgirb eht otni tniuqs dna nepo eye eno kcarc I
.em htiw ereht neeb dah uoy fi uoy ksa ot noitseuq riafnu na neeb evah dluow ti dna
.dnuorg ytsud dna dekcarc eht ot sllaf ti neht dna
”.ytnuob nwo rieht ni erahs dna
htaerb peed a ekat I
,noisnetxe larberec ym otni dedaolnwod scitamehcs eht dah ydaerla I ,ylikcuL
,tnemecalper eht nees dah uoy emit tsrif eht saw tI
.gnol retemolik a revo enil a ni derettacs ,dop epacse ym fo stnanmer eht ees dna
,ereh fo tuo ti ekam lliw I .okarA ,hO
.ylbatrofmocnu gurhs uoY .kaorc I
.tuo dnif ot evah t’nod I taht os krow ot teg ot dna
.erusaem gnivas-rewop emos fo esuaceb ro yletarebiled rehtie
.nrot sedis sti fo eno ,dehctarcs ylivaeh ,egakcerw eht ni erutcip ruoy dnif I
,ecaf ruoy no kool gums a enigami I
ni dnuof eb nac krow tnecer tsom esohw ,enrohtwaH .S.J yb
.stnalp daed fo lluf tresed eht dna nus yrgna ,gninrub eht evah ylno I
”?he ,sesor pu gninrut si gnihtyrevE“
.dnuorgelttab ruo emoceb dah yeht taht
.niaga ecaf ruoy ees em tel tub
.tuo ylraen era tik lavivrus eht ni snoitar eht dna ,ecalp nerrab siht ni doof sa elbaifitnedi gnihton dnif I
.os gniod fo yromem yna
,evol ruo ni edirp tuohtiw ,edirp tuohtiw
elzzum ym no tnemelffab eht enigami ylluf ot elba era uoy epoh I
.noitamrofni lufesu fo stros lla em gnivig era stnalpmi ym tub
,noitcerid etisoppo
,edis ym ta ereht era uoy neht dna
.evol ym ,gnikat m’I troffe eht etaicerppa uoy epoh I
.ecnatsid elbaicerppa yna erehpsomta eht fo edistuo tsacdaorb dluow taht eno ton ,reviecsnart a dliub t’nac I
,taen eht ,eciov ruoy fo noitcelfni lacisum ,eltneg eht enigami ,eciov ruoy enigami nac I  .uoy ekil hcuM
.rerutcafunam eht ot drac uoy knaht a dnes ot tnaw uoy esac ni ,okarA ,eton a ekaM
,seye ym nepo ot elggurts I
.devlovni secrof eht fo thguoht eht ta redduhs I
.niaga gnildwad ma I taht em llet dluow uoy ,ereh erew uoy fI
ylluferac ti kcut I
.stnenopmoc emorhc gninihs
.tuo gnihtemos gnilzzup era uoy nehw teg uoy ecaf suoires taht ,tnemeerga ni gniddon uoy enigami I
seno nekorb owt fo tuo ten gnikrow eno ekam ot kniht ot laiceps taht lla eb ot em ot mees t’nseod ti—
,ni ekowa I retarc worran eht fo pil eht ot bmilc I
”,efink loot-itlum a otni
”?nalaK ,gnippots uoy era yhw nehT“  .uoy ksa I
,kraps t’now ti won
lluh fo knuhc a morf tuo tik lavivrus eht gid I sa noitarapes taht tuoba kniht I
.retaw eht fo tsal eht knurd evah I retfa si ti taht ylno
,mra eht ni peed etiuq si tI
.egalliv dnalsi na no
”,em devas uoY“  ”.dneirf dlo nA“
msahc mid lanoisacco eht yb ylno nekorb kcor dekcarc fo tresed denrub a si flesti epacsdnal ehT
.egakcerw rednu deppart teg ot liat fo retem a ton s’ereht tsael tA
pu gnirb ot tnatropmi os demees yllaer reven ti neht dna
,ylper d’uoy tahw si ”,elbuorT“
.thgir ti ekam t’nseod taht tub
dlrow a si etats sdrocer cilbupeR eht tahw no etis a ot yaw ruo no ,rosseforp rehtona dna flesym
kcab ym htaeneb dnuorg ykcor eht yb tnemom a rof desufnoc
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT .htnoM edirP ot
.depacse diulf eht erehw seriw dna snotsip eht gnola sliart krad era ereht dna ,nepo nekorb era sciluardyh eht fo tsoM
tub‘ - noitseuq eht emoc lliw ereht ,ti ees ot evah ot ton hguone etanutrof era ew fi neve ,raey yreve ,ylbativenI
.rettimsnart tfihsekam ym hguorht ti tsacdaorb neht
,ssetseirp gninrub ym
,did I fi neve dna mra ym xif ot sloot on evah I
keew a deyaled saw segassem ruoy fo hcae tub—
.sserttam toc elbatrofmoc ym fo daetsni
,uoy fo tnemgif eht ksa I
hcA“  .em ot etirw uoy sa neve sretcarahc cilbupeR railimafnu eht ward ot woh rebmemer uoy sa rettuts emehparg tfos eht
s’erehT .tih I hcihw ,esaeler ycnegreme na sah mra yM
,mra eht elbmessasid ylluf ot moor elpma em sdroffa kcor ehT
?evol ruo no gnidurtni pots dluow sralloc rieht no aingisni knar eznorb-neerg htiw sregnarts taht oS
.duola yas I ”,doog ton s’tahT“
ffo tup ev’I em llet dluow uoy
.siht evivrus lliw I fi wonk t’nod I dna
.pu ti ekam I os ,laer ton er’yeht esuaceb ,t’nod I .em ksa uoy dneterp I
,srettat ni ffo gnignah si gnirevoc rehtaew rehtael-xuaf ehT
.rood eht fo tuo sehsinav dna swob eh dna
.raw eht tfihs ot meti elbaesu yna fo tnih tsethgils eht
dna hcum oot si thgil eht tub
.fo dnof os era sepyt ycarcoeht uoy taht eman ym fo evitunimid egnarts taht gnisu ,yas dluow uoy
.ti pac ot yaw a dnif nac I dedivorp
eht dna pot eht hcaer I nehw
.niaga revo lla uoy htiw evol ni llaf dluow I
,tresed eht pu kaerb ot gnihton ees I .yaw ytpme
,niap yna leef t’nod I dna srosnes ym morf strela yna gnitteg ton m’I tsael ta ro
,mra reppu eht nacs dna xob rellortnoc eht no pu evig I
.redluohs ym revo gnikool uoy enigami I
.esoppus I ,deirrac rO
.lleh siht morf em ediug lliw taht evol ruoy si tI
rebmemer yltnatsnoc ot evah ot naht scinortcele ruoy htiw gnilddif saw I nehw ereh siht kcut ot reisae saw tI
ehs erehw ,nodotsaM no dnuof eb ylisae tsom nac ehS
,tcatni yltsom devivrus dop eht fo gniliec eht fo noitrop A
?yas uoy dluow tahW
.erom elttil a gniworruf worb ruoy
.egakcerw eht gniyevrus tuoba tes I sa raw taht tuoba kniht I
ssap syad owT  .ereh
.sruoy ni wap ym ekat dna tuo hcaer neht ,ylluferac seye eht ni em kool dluow uoY
,toh os ton spahrep ,lleW
.tsrif nocaeb ssertsiD
,yrtne-er no ti deppilc evah tsum dop epacse ym erehw gnikoms llits
eht wonk t’nod I tuB
oediv a devas I dnif ot dekcohs m’I
.evol ym ,em htiw ereh erew uoy hsiw I
.yad txen eht eucser on si erehT
,tseb ta ecracs si retaW
”.emit htiw ,yrevocer lluf a ekam ll’uoy yas scirelc eht tub ,detardyhed yrev erew uoY .tser dluohs uoY“
.srettel eht no tup uoy stnemnroda elttil yrassecennu eht
,em emalb t’nod uoy wonk I .yaw eht yb ,taht tuoba yrros ma I
.yawyna emoc yeht tub ,sraet eht enigami ton od I
.pu em sekaw tahT
.ti tsoob ot yaw a deen llits I
drow ym evah uoy ,kcor etalosed siht ffo ti ekam I gnimussA
.gnitirw tuoba klat ot sekil
?evol ym ,od I od tahW
.efil fo dioved tenalp tresed a no enola m’I esuaceb pu demaerd ev’I gnihtemos er’uoy ,em rof ecivda evah t’nac uoy esruoc fO
.spil ruoy ssik dna niaga dnah ruoy dloh em teL
smra ym ni uoy dloh nac I os
.dnif ot elba m’I tib elttil eht noitar ylluferac ot decrof m’I dna
.meht htiw yalp ot ,meht leef ot ,sgniht dloh ot ekil I .tcnitsni ym ton si sihT
.tuo gnits eht ekat ot nirg a dna tnemmoc elttil prahs a evah t’nod I dna su fo reittiw eht er’uoy dna
.tnet a pu tes I nehT  .esac ni tsuJ
,evol tuohtiw esuaceb
,ereh erew uoy fI
,sdaer eton eht ”,nalaKh-
.trats eht morf gniod neeb evah dluohs ew tahw s’taht nwonk evah dluow ylbaborp uoy ereh yllautca erew uoy fi ,lleH
.em htiw ereh yllautca er’uoy
,pihs eht fo edistuo thgil fo hsalf a s’erehT
.em sraeh enoemos taht epoh dna
.wonk t’nod I tahw eticer tonnac I dna
.erutcip ruoy depat ev’I hcihw ot elosnoc eht ni detcelfer
.hsif ot ytiliba eht tuohtiw meht gnivael
,yks eht ni srats era ereht era srewsna gnol ynam sa era erehT
,meht ot teg ot yaw a tuo erugif nac I fi ,ereht ni stnenopmoc lufesu emos era erehT
,dedispol leef I
,luos ym ,traeh ym ,okarA
.gnitalp eht fo smaes eht ot teg nac I taht os trid eht fo tuo ti gid ot sruoh wef a sekat ti hguoht
.sirbed fo enil eht ta talf nepo eht fo tuo gnirats
,depahs diolobarap t’nsi flesti dop ehT
,nus larutan a htiw tenalp a no neeb ev’I ecnis edaced a ot esolc neeb sah tI
,semit nezod a eton eht daerer dna daer I  ”.okarA
tuoba noitasrevnoc a ni dessorgne ,noitanitsed ruo fo pam yevrus a gninimaxe er’eW
?llew gnikrow t’nsaw ti nehw ti htiw reknit ot desu uoy woh rebmemeR
.niaga gnirevoc a raew reve lliw I kniht t’nod I dna
.em gnivig er’uoy erutcel denigami eht fo tuo ssenprahs eht gnikat tnecca ycarcoehT lacisum taht ,raelc latsyrc os ,eciov ruoy enigami I sa elims I
.senob-xuaf eht ot nwod
”eriF deohcE ekiL evoL“   yojne esaelP
”?emaN-oN tniaS fo yrots eht wonk uoy oD“
,sruoy fo liat knuks kciht ylsuoiruxul taht deivne netfo evah I ,tseraed ,yas tsum I
.eno gnivig eht syawla erew uoy neht tub
.mra siht fo stnenopmoc eht htiw pihsecaps eritne na
annetna eht fo thgis nihtiw yats I
.teb tseb ym si lluh renni eht ni muinatiT
margoloh a si llaw raf eht nO
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.pal ym ni bmil lacinahcem eht fo snoitcennoc etaciled eht odnu ot yaw on ,sloot on evah I
,sekat ti revetahw ,ot evah uoy tahw oD
”eriF deohcE ekiL evoL“
,enrohtwaH .S.J yb ”eriF deohcE ekiL evoL“ saw sihT
.retarc eht fo egde tseraen eht morf sretem ytriht
.thgiew ruoy eciwt setarip htiw
,ffo gniht eht ekat tsael ta nac I
evaw I ”,ereht nwod ,oN“
.hcum ton s’erehT
,eciffo fo elots ruoy ni selknirw fo tsetniaf eht
.hguone esolc s’ti tub ,yltcefrep citamehcs eht hctam t’nseod tI
.smarg eerht naht erom hgiew t’nac taht loot a yrrac ot yzal oot gnieb rof uoy ta lley ot ylno
”.ot em tnaw uoy sa gnol sa roF“
,uoy-fo-efiw eht ,narA“
.yawa sretem wef a redluob talf yltsom a ot etacoler I dna
taht stenalp fo lufdnah a
.dezinagro dna detros yltaen lla sgniht segnarra ohw eno eht er’uoY
.annetna deef a dna rettimsnart eht gnidliub tneps si gnineve ym fo tser ehT
,yks eht fo tuo spord enoemos litnu lufsseccus m’I fi wonk t’nac I ,reviecer a tuohtiW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,tnemeerga ni gniddon er’uoy dneterp I
mrots eht morf sten nekorb eht fo lla pu derehtag emaN-oN tniaS ,deugra yeht elihW“
.sthgilhgih der htiw hguorht tohs
.em gnillet uoy dneterp ot gnideen tuohtiw
?tahw neht tub ,gulpnu nac I ecruos rewop ehT
?ecalp siht epacse tonnac I fi“
,ereh fo tuo ti ekam lliw I
.yrgna taht nus a htiw erehwyna neeb reve ev’I eveileb t’nod I dna
.senal taerg eht ni kcatta na gnitcepxe ton
.deniwtne era sluos yrev ruO
,wef a gnitcennocsid ,seriw eht htiw elbmuf I
.yrtne cirehpsomta eht ro hsarc eht rehtie morf gnikoms llits si ti fo hcuM
,rewsna gnol eno rof tub
.daeha drow tnes yeht dna resiurc cilbupeR a yb pu dekcip saw eugaelloc ruoY“
,emos gniyfirup dna gnitcelloc tuoba
,ecaps gnihcaer si noissimsnart ym rehtehw dna erehpsomta eht fo noitisopmoc cificeps eht wonk t’nod I—wonk I ,pu teg sepoh ym tel t’nac I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tresed neila na no denooram neeb ev’uoy retfa em egduj nac uoy tub ,em morf nosrep etarapes a sa tnemgif siht gnitaert eb ton dluohs ylbaborp I
.gniyas uoy enigami I ”,oN“
,laer t’nsi taht uoy a ksa ot noitseuq riafnu na s’tI
.meht dnatsrednu od I tub ,okarA ,sdrow ruoy etalsnart tonnac I
gnidneterp m’I taht eciton ot ton drah yrev yrt I .em llet uoy
.nosaer doog a rof si ti raews I tub
ereh ton er’uoy tuB
.tnetsixenon ot mils era tenalp eht ta gnivaw yllautca m’I secnahc eht taht erawa ylluf ,yleugav
,emalF yloH eht fo serutpircs
:ecno ta secalp owt ni flesym dnif
.cilbupeR ym fo egaugnal ,citeop ssel hcum dna ,lacigol erom hcum eht otni noitalsnart sedave noitatulas ruoy dna
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ti dellatsni ohw scinahcem eht neve ton
.ereht tog reve I erofeb gnol dezingocer evah dluow uoy gnimussa m’I dna gnikniht m’I hcihw ro ,gnikniht htob er’ew sdrow eht yas ew dna
,nwo rieht no evivrus ot woh revo derehtid srehto elihW
dna oediv eht ssecca I
,revo llor I sa naorg I   enrohtwaH .S.J yb
.won ti fo tfel gnihtyna eb t’now erehT
dna sitseV no rehtegot tog ew emit taht rebmemeR .esrow ni neeb ev’I“
.rethgual lacisum ruoy si
em morf lufrae na teg ot gniog er’uoy ezilaer uoy epoh I
,sdor rieht dna staob s’egalliv eht deyortsed hcihw mrots elbirret a saw ereht ,yad enO
.detner I rethgierf elttil eht fo ssensselthgiew elbatrofmoc eht ni dna tenalp gninrub a fo ecaf eht no
.niarb ym ni dees taht detnalp uoy tub—
.tiuspmuj ym fo tekcop a otni
?t’ndluow I taht ,evol ym ,ees uoy dluow tahW
”,ecivda yna evah uoy fI“
.ti ekil gnihtemos ro
:noitpo ysae eht htiw trats I
”.kniht I ,gnivivrus no krow tseB“
,okarA tseraed yM
”.tcurtsni ot tnaem s’ti
.dop epacse na otni gnivid m’I neht dna ,barg I gniht tsal eht si erutcip ruoY
.tnaw uoy sa wol sa erutarepmet eht tes ot teg llahs uoy taht
”,nalaK ,elbarap a s’tI“
.niaga enim tsniaga ydob ruoy tuoba nialpmoc reven lliw I ,siht fo tuo ti ekam I fI .ssetseirp lufituaeb ym ,okarA ym ,okarA ,hO
,epahs yreve fo sdneirf ,emocleW
”,thgirla si tI“  .emalF yloH ehT
bmil dengised llew yltcefrep a mrofsnart ot dengised ecnavirtnoc sselesu A“
ybsressap ot gninetsil dna uoy htiw gnittis fo yoj eht evah em teL
nees reve evah I gnihtyna ot neila yllatot era ereh stnalp ehT
.mra sselesu ym no llits si noitartnecnoc ym hguoht
.eucser tuoba kniht
.emitnaem eht ni meht niatsus ot doof elttil evah dluow yeht dna
t’nod I ,peelsa llaf I sA
.emalf evissam ,elgnis a fo
,sesoprup ym rof tneiciffus eb lliw senoc muinatit eht fo eno ynA
em stel DUH ym dna
.seirrac pihs ym dop epacse fo elyts eht no selohtrop xis era erehT
evolg a ekil ti esu dna yletelpmoc ffo revoc rehtael eht knay si od nac I llA
,alaK ruoy ,ekil gnihtemoS
,eganam I ”?okarA
yletamixorppa si ti em sllet retemonorhc lanretni yM
.enam a fo ffup noilednad a htiw noil a ta pu tniuqs ot nrut I dna ,syas eciov eht
,meht dnuora delkcub sah dop eht fo tser eht tub ,enif ylbaborp era senoc muinatit ehT .ni devac si
,ssim I taht sgniht elttil eht eciton syawla uoY
ti ot erom s’ereht erus m’I
.pihs on si ereht taht emussa ot evah osla I os ,retupmoc s’pihs eht ot noitcennoc on s’erehT
,selohtrop eht gnidulcni ,dne tnorf ehT
gnihtemoS ?ycarcoehT eht fo egaugnal eht taht sI  ”!hsnev-harem hkat seshkevI !narA ,ev rU !narA“ ,lworg fo tnih a ,eciov a semoc ”!hA“
:si rewsna trohs eht
,mra ruoy fo erac retteb koot uoy fI
.yab ecnanetniam a tuohtiw kcab ti tup ot yaw a evah t’nod I hguoht
.ti ta kool t’nod I dna redluohs ym morf gnignah thgiew sselesu fo smargolik eerht si mra tfel yM
,ecafrus ylekil a yfitnedi dna dop epacse ym fo egakcerw eht nacs ylkciuq em tel stnemecnahne ym
.od ot tahw revo syad rof deugra sredle egalliv ehT
,krow drah fo shtnom gnol ynam ekat dluow taht tub ,esruoc fo ,dliuber dluoc yehT
elkcuhc dluow uoy ,ereh erew uoy fI
,hcamots ym snrut thgis ehT
.trats ll’I erehw s’taht os
,taht retfa yad ehT  .doof on tub
,laretil eb ot tnaem ton s’tI“
,noitacinummoc oN
.nekorb si mra tfel ym snaem
,ti delrufnu dna dnalsi rieht no niatnuom tsellat eht ot debmilc neht yehT
,okarA ,em tfel uoy loot eht deniur ylraen yrev evah I hcihw ni ,krow drah fo yad rehtonA
.ti no dial uoy nehw peelsa gnillaf mra ym tuoba nialpmoc ot dewolla t’nsaw I em dlot dna dehgual dah uoy dna
”.ynnub ,ni flesruoy dnuof ev’uoy ssem a etiuQ“
tsael tA .ffo ti hctiws dna retrevnoc rewop eht dnif I sa
.sdne oediv eht neht dna
naem uoY“  ”.semoc ehs
?evol ym ,rebmemer uoy oD .kcab sraey wef
,snoitatiseh elttil eht nevE
.seilppus doof gnildniwd ym llifer ot troffe ym elbuoder I sa
,slriws dna spoows lufituaeb ,etaciled sti dna gnitirwdnah railimaf ruoy ta gnillirht ,eton eht daer I  .ydob ym fo edisni
,ecaps lanimulrepus hguorht gnillevart si pu gnikaw erofeb yromem tsal yM
.mra tfel ym ta kool dna
.tnelat ym ton s’tahT .traeh ym ,suineg lacinahcem eht era uoY
snoitcennoc eht htiw gniyalp trats d’uoy dna seye ym esolc
neht dna ,erehpsomta eht epacse ot hguone noissimsnart eht tsoob dluohs ti ,kcul elttil a htiW
,denigami evah I uoy eht ksa I ”,od I od tahW“
.efil ym devas ylekil dna ,ereht si dop epacse eht fo tnorf ehT
,elims uoY  ”.em htiw yatS“
deyortsed tnempiuqe eht ecalper pleh ot emac ohw
,tuo ssap I nehw wonk t’nod I
.erad dluow eno oN
.tnalp gnikool-daed dna ybburcs ro
.thgir tsuj ti dah uoy litnu
.gnihsalf deppots sah DUH ym ni rosnes gninraw eht tsael ta tub
.emalF dercaS eht fo htmraw eht morf raf
”,niseV lwaC pohsibhcrA“
rehsif a saw emaN-oN tniaS“
”?uoy tuohtiw evil I nac woh ,evrats t’nod I fi nevE
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.nac I gnihtyreve enod evah I uoy esimorp I ,traeh ym ,okarA
daeh nwo ym otni gnillaf m’I taht si ,esruoc fo ,yas dluow uoy tahW
pu kcap dna ylrae pu ekaw I
,emit lasrevinu sruoh 0371
.ni m’I regnad eht tegrof em ekam ot ssenlaer on ,htmraw on ,thgiew on sah wap yranigami ruoY
”?kniht uoy od tahW“
.emas eht si uoy-tnemgif siht epoh I dna
.esoppus I ,ereht ron ereh rehtien s’tahT
,niaga diov eht otni tuo egassem ym gnidnes nigeb dna
”?uoy od ,ereh hsif hcum ees t’nod I tub ,yrots ylevol A“
.ereht egatnavda eno evah od seinnub su tub ,llab nottoc elttil nwo ym detnemal dna
,decnaun ,detacilpmoc si ycarcoehT ruoy fo egaugnal ehT …nalaKh-hcA
.em evig d’uoy hgis eht raeh nac I
.lufepoh ,retarc taht ni pu ekow I ecnis emit tsrif eht rof ,leef I tub
?tahw neht ,stnenopmoc eht ta teg dluoc I fi nevE
lla neht dna ,pihs eht stih elitcejorp eht sa hsalf dnoces a si erehT
.tuo dekcalb ,yltnerappa ,I erofeb deton saw atad lausiv emos ebyam—
.latem ot eriw nekorb morf dessap evah tsum rewop evil erehw secalp ni sehcrocs krad era ereht dna
.parcs fo elip a dna ehcadaeh a si em sevig ti lla tub
.eno dnif nac I fi enoc a pac ot llew od lliw taht elffab munimula na dnif od I
dna leets dna muinatit krad gnilaever
?nepo eniw eht teg t’ndluoc ew nehw dellatsni wercskroc a gnivah tuoba em gnisaet rebmemer uoy oD ?eveileb I
,rehtegot meht deit eh dna
’?htnom edirp a deen uoy od yhw
…swolla taht msinahcem ehT
.em ot sselesu s’ti tsael ta ro ,sselesu si siht fo tsoM
,em fo hsifles eb thgim tI
tuohtiw noisnetxe larberec ym ot
,okarA ym ,weivrup ruoy si tahT .sreyarP htraeH eht wonk t’nod I
,rettimsnart fo dnik a ydaerla si mra ym lortnoc ot em …dewolla
noisnetxe larberec ym ni scitamehcs s’pihs dedaolnwod eht dna
.lootitlum etaciled a gnilaever ,tfel uoy eton eht parwnu I sa
,ecnareviled rof ytied ruoy ot yarp I tub
,dereves era scinahcem eht dna
,gnihtyreve dloh ot hguone egral ton si pal yM
.snus neila eht fo thgil hsrah eht ni elbisivni tsomla dna ynit
eht ni gnihcnual si dop epacse rehtonA
a ni gnilims s’eH
.ecalp siht ni esahcrup on sdnif taht nus a fo ygrene gnivig-efil eht htiw gniwolg dnal daed ,sseldne ylno
deciton neve reven ylbaborp
,asem eht tih taht trap eht ylbaborp ,sedis eht fo enO
”.ereh m’I taht kcul ylno s’tI .noitarepo tnioj a neeb s’tI
.sdrow ruoy fo tuo gnits eht ekat dluow taht dna em htiw derahs reve ylno uoy taht nirg taht erahs d’uoy tub—
.egaugnal ym gnihctiws ,em llet uoy
dna kcab nael em evah d’uoy ywercs tnew snoitcennoc yrosnes eht revenehW
* * *  .emit erom eno uoy ees ot ylno fi
tluaf ym saw ti woh tuoba tnemmoc prahs a
,srobhgien s’dnalsi rieht morf dia denommus emaN-oN tniaS
.ti morf yawa hcnilf I
,elbirret a ni lufituaeb s’tI
,ycarcoehT ruoy dna cilbupeR eht neewteb egde eht no ,dnif gniticxe nA
.nees reve evah I gniht lufituaeb tsom eht si ti dna
.hguoht ,redluohs ym morf nwod gnignah latem fo knuh nekorb a evah llits I
,noitasrevnoc ruo ni degagne oot er’ew ,ti eciton flesym fo noisrev tsap eht ron munelaC rehtieN
.yrd oot si taorht ym tub
,annetna eht gnidulcni ,esle gnihtyrevE
,sllik ycarcuaerub taht si ereh nossel eht dnA“
tiaw ot deen tsuj I
.uoy denigami ylno evah I taht ,tegrof ot gniyrt ro ,gnittegrof
,tuo sciluardyh nekorb eht fo emos gnillup
gnittes tsuj si nus ehT .htlaeh ot kcab em esrun ot ereh uoy tuohtiw gel a kaerb ot etah d’I .emas eht lla eb nac I sa luferac sa ma I tub ,bmilc tluciffid ylralucitrap a ton
?dettimsnart eb ot ti timrep dluow tnemnrevog ruoy
:tcepser tnatropmi yrev eno ni ,evol ym ,gnorw era uoY  ”.rotcelfeR“
.sR ruoy llirt uoy yaw eltbus eht ,slewov deppilc
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb
.uoy evol I .okarA ,eciov ruoy evol I
ton era uoy taht tegrof tonnac I
.trats ot erehw aedi doog a em sevig
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.sevaw oidar eht ecnuob t’ndluow taht syolla evitcudnoc-non morf edam si ti fo tsom
.ti raeh ot yb hguone esolc ssap lliw enoyna rehtehw enola tel
won si tahw fo tuo nwod deruces ton gnihtyna wolb ot snigeb noisserpmoced fo dniw neddus eht sa neve retupmoc elbatrop eht barg I elihw ,srepap dna spam fo lufdnah a sbarg munelaC .soahc si
,denigami evah I uoy eht esaet I ”?taht tuoba erutpircs fo eceip ydnah emos evah uoy t’noD“
?taht ekil gnihtemos ot yas uoy nac tahW
.slaunam lavivrus ym ot devas s’taht ro
.ytefas ot laC gniyrrac yllufepoh
peelsa llaf I erofeb raeh I gniht tsal ehT ”.reveroF“
.323 etad radnelac
tes dna retaw fo sloop yddum erom wef a dnif ot eganam I
,yas ot yrt I ”?ohW“
,asem a si ecnatsid eht nI
?netfo erom eciov ruoy raeh dluoc I os ,retsaf emoc dluow segassem ruoy os
”’.ria eht ni ti etsat nac ew rehto hcae htiw evol ni os era nemow
edam evah dluoc uoy tbuod on ,evol ym ,rereknit eht er’uoY
.sesoprup ym rof tpada ot ysae yllufknaht dna
.decalper siht teg I nehw dedda eno evah ot erus ekam ll’I
.siht ekil yrev saw ti enigami dluohs I did I fi tub ,evol ym ,sehcaerp noigiler ruoy lleh eht ni deveileb reve evah I kniht t’nod I .okarA on ,mra on ,srosnes on
.edisni stiucric dna seriw fo ssem eht etagivan
”?setarip esoht htiw lwarb a otni tog
.suremuh a sa snoitcnuf taht dor muinatit eht dnuora parw taht seriw fo eldnub eht otni dekcut
,rosseforp eht htiw aera lartnec eht ni m’I
”,rettimsnart eht fo htgnerts eht tsoob ot
.ees I tahw ees uoy sa kcohs ruoy enigami I
,yggarc dna hguor si tI   .asem eht ot og I nehT  .tsiaw ym ot eit I hcihw ,kcap lavivrus eht ni seog
.eno ,lanigiro ,rehto eht naht relap edahs a tsuj ,eye decalper ruoy fo wolg mid eht
,tnet ym ni gnildduh emit ym dneps I
.eil scinortcele ,elbissecca erom yllufepoh dna ,etaciled ssel erehw
.munelaC fo eman eht yb
,ereh erew uoy fI
.eerf meht tuc nac I erofeb tuo raew yletinifed lliw lootitlum eht dna
.eno elttil eht tub ,naem I ,raw gib eht toN ?okarA tseraed
.mrofinu ruoy htiw deyalp ev’uoy woh morf ralloc ruoy dnuora ruf fo gnihcnub eht
,sruoy fo niarb lufrednow taht ot gnihtyna gnidda enigami t’nac uoy dna em rof doog on era sedargpu eseht taht em gnillet peek uoy wonk I
.ti ekirts selitcejorp erom nezod a sa neve
noisiv ym ni gnirevoh thgil der gnihsalf eht ,elpmaxe roF
,tcatni eb ot smees em fo tser ehT
,ereht ton er’uoY
.siht htiw dop ym riaper t’nac I
seiceps dna ,redneg ,ytiliba
erofeb ecnegilletni fo slevel eerht hguorht dessap eb ot gnivah em tnes uoy euqinummoc yreve rebmemer uoy oD
.emalF dercaS eht fo tnerehda tuoved a tuoba
,deppans era seriw lareveS
.edis eht ot ffo taht hsup I os ,em ot gniziteppa ylralucitrap si ereh gnihton tub ,ytsriht dna yrgnuh teg ot gnitrats m’I
,noitcurtsed fo enil eht klaw ot yad eht fo tser eht fo tsom em sekat tI
a renilrats taht no koot ew noitacav taht tuoba kniht I ,daetsnI
?kniht I ,ekawa gnieb tuoba
,ot kaeps ot esle enoyna evah t’nod I esuaceb ,denigami ev’I uoy eht ot kaeps I
.shtgnel hcus ot og ot deen ton dluow I
.em devas uoy taht uoy llet dna uoy ssik dna
,sehctiwt liat ruoy yaw ralucitrap eht no pu kcip dluow esle enoyna kniht t’nod I
.pleh fo egassem a tuo gnilleps sehtolc eht
.trats ot ecalp a tniopnip ot gniyrt
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.devivrus evah ton dluoc ew
hguoht ,uoy ni cinap eht ees nac I
,rehtie ,tuo ma I gnol woh wonk t’nod I
fo lortnoc rof gniyv ,enim dna eripme ruoY
.niaga taht od reven lliw I tub ,rehtegot evael erohs tsal ruo no lortnoc etamilc eht tuoba denialpmoc I wonk I ,evol ym ,uoy esimorp I .toh rO
riah nrubua htiw lerriuqs yknal a
ees nac I .em htiw noitalosed eht yevrus uoy sa liat ruoy fo hctiwt detatirri eht ,noisserpxe nrets ruoy enigami nac I
.suoicsnocnu saw I emussa ot evah I os ,emit fo ,tsael ta ,yad doog a gnissim m’I
”nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI“
fi sseug neve ot noitamrofni hguone evah t’nod I
era rellortnoc dna srosnes ehT
.daehrevo sgnah llab der-egnaro gnizalb a ,lenap-wolg deziretupmoc a fo thgil ylraep looc eht fo daetsnI .oot
,noitamrofni fo lesrom tseinit eht neve rof ti tcessid ot ecnegilletnI rof
,evol tsetaerg htiW
”.ti erahs ot emit doog a eb dluow won“
.mraw rehto hcae peek dna pac eci na otni nibac ruo nrut s’tel—neve rewoL
sthgif kcip ot ton uoy llet dna sgnittes erutarepmet eht tuoba nialpmoc em tel ,msacras ym htiw hgual uoy ekam em teL
stfig em gnivael tuoba
.noitcerid yna ni noziroh eht ot ees nac I lla si taht tub
.yticirtceleoib nwo ym pu esu ot snigeb ti dna tuo sevig yrettab eht nehw evrats t’now I dna
,piuq elttil a evah d’uoY
.gniyas er’yeht tahw dnatsrednu t’nod I tub ,em raen gniklat fo dnuos tfos eht ot ekaw I nehw dna
.noitalupop fo drocer on sah taht
pmuj neddus a s’erehT
,enilffo si noisnetxe larberec yM
,thgirb oot si yks ehT
.yroeht rotinegorp ym rof ecnedive eb thgim taht
.evila em peek ot devivrus dop eht fo hguone taht levram I
strap doolb-dna-hself ym neewteb snoitcennoc eht sa noitasnes gnilwarc egnarts a ,ssih tfos a
,thgir tsuj detsujda ti teg reve dluoc esle eno oN
.tem ew revenehw loot a kcap ot
.kcab dna asem eht ot yaw eht lla ti gnicart
,tsrif rettimsnart eht pu tes I
.flah ni deppir neeb sah enoc eht taht degamad ylhguoroht os si
.rebmemer uoy ,sey ,em llet dna daeh ruoy ekahs dna
.taht ekil eucser a teg ot ylekil ton m’I metsys ralos eht tsap sneppah gnihtemos sselnu tub ,trats a s’tahT