,ti ni erusaelp on ekat lliw I
.yam I yademos yrrow I
.kcen ym fo ffurcs eht ta skcil eugnot ypsar ruoY
.revihs uoy dna ,yas I ",si ti woN"
.taeb ton seod taht traeh a htiw ehtaerb ton seod taht ydob dloc a
,erit I sa ksa uoy
.evila ma llits I
.egde eht drawot rehtruf uoy sevird hsup hcaE
,uoy hsivar ot tnaw tsuj I
.uoy fo edisni flesym tneps evah I retfa
.em morf yawa knirhs t'nod uoy tub
"?cidaR ,tey emit ti sI"
.ylirgnuh sgnaf ym kcil I
.rof regnuh yletarepsed os I taht htmraw ruoy fo tib elttil a em gnivig tnemom hcaE
,kcen ruoy sezarg htuom ym
…tey dna ,srae ym ni gnos evitcudes a
...tey dna ,reverof em ot uoy dnib ot flesym fo elttil a uoy evig neht dna ,uoy fo lla knird ylno deen I
.tfel gnihton eb dluow ereht litnu ni uoy knird ot tnaw I
,em stnuat evila uoy speek taht doolb ehT
.esruc siht fo flesym eerf nac I fi ees ot eruc a rof kool ot emit evah llits I elihw toN
evah I tub ,semit nezod tsrif eht cigam saw ti thguoht I
.yzarc em gnivird tsurht hcae
.saw I ekil uoy esruc t'nac I .t'nevah I
.siht dennalp uoy os ,yawa ti tup uoy wonk I
.ysatsce ni tuhs ezeeuqs seye ruoY
,dlrow siht detaerc taht sdog eht esruc em sekam feirb os si ti tcaf ehT
.pu flesym enil I sa ,em dnuora smra ruoy parw uoY
,oot taht rof uoy etah I .em
.osla su tsniaga si emit wonk I
noitapicitna ni sehsal liat ruoY
.hguoht nialpmoc t'nod uoY
dluow I .flesym evigrof reven dluow I tey dna ,lla ti ekat ot kciuq os ,ysae eb dluow tI
niaga evila leef em sekam tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.uoy niard yllanif I nehw ti fo tnemom yreve etah lliw I tub ,em stpmet ti
.uoy htiw ma I tey dna ,uoy rof gnorw ma I ,revol drapoel yM
,deifsitas uoy ees ot
,efil morf tfel teg nac I lla si siht fi tub
tsol ev'I gnihtyreve fo em sdnimer tI
”gnorW si uoY gnivoL“   :yojne esaelP
.ylgnilliw ecnad siht od htob ew tey dna
,od I yaw eht leef reve ot uoy hsiw ton od I
,uoy tsniaga pu lruc I sa dna ,nus eht ssim I
,ereh yats nac ew sa gnol sA
,era uoy emit yreve dna
ruf ym otni gniggid swalc ruoy
.em polevne ruf ruoy ni stnecs eht tel dna esolc teg I daetsni os ,em er'uoy nehw yppah gnieb hguot s'tI
,yrgnuh ma I .eil I ",oN"
.nialpmoc ton od uoy tey dna ,merkE
,uoy htiw wohemos tub
,rehtegot deniwtne gniyl er'ew sa ,yas uoy
.merkE ,em ot uoy nokceb dna elims ylno nac I
,steehs eht no ereht gniyl uoy htiW
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.moc.gnirpsyad-seyethgin
.yrgnuh ma I tub ,erac dluohs I
,uoy tsniaga dloc si hcuot ym wonk I
.em yfsitas ot hguone tnetop ton s'ti fi neve ,gniog em peek lliw tI
.nialpmoc reven uoy tub
.thgiled yreppoc taht etsat dna etib ot egru eht tsiser ot evah I
"?cidaR ,knird ot deen uoy oD"
,deb eht no uoy ot pu elgguns I sa ,retaL
uoy eviltuo llahs I
.evol dna ecarg htiw uoy fo edisni em emoclew uoY
.thgilnus dna ,sevael
,uoy ekil drapoel a htiw roirefni leef ylisae dluoc flesym ekil xof A
.yaw rehto on ti tnaw dluow I tey dna
.ta sseug ylno nac uoy syaw ni em secitne
.gnorw s'ti fi neve ,uoy evol I
,erusaelp ni tuo naom uoY   .hguone eb lliw ti
.egalliv eht ni nwod elttac emos kcatta dna
si yrots s’yadot dna ,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,eno evah llits I fi ,luos yM
.stnemom eseht ni tnaw I hcihw taht ton s'ti
,tcefrep syawla si gnimit ruoy wohemoS
.tfil sgel ruoy dna
.srae ym ni gnidnuop ti raeh nac I ,duol os staeb traeh ruoY
.yltsenoh erac regnol on I
dnah eht yb em ekat uoY
,merkE ,uoy htiW .od I
?em htiw yats uoy od yhW
.em ot sllac ti dna
,uoy fo pot no bmilc I
gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
.em evig t'now uoy gnihtyreve dna
,yawa knirhs reven uoY
,htrae ekil llems uoy ,xes retfa nevE
.em nokceb uoy daetsnI
.drah steg tfahs ruoy dna
,mraw si ydob ruoy ni doolb ehT
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
.luos a evah llits I kniht I
.niks ruoy woleb tsuj
.merkE ,uoy ot emoc mrah on ees ot hsiw I tub
,em stnuat ydob ruoy ni doolb mraw ehT
niaga enola ,dlrow siht ni ,ereh eb llits lliw I dna enog eb lliw uoy yademos dna
,gnorw si siht tuoba gnihtyrevE
,ti od ot em geb uoy semitemos wonk I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.emit yreve revihs uoY
,erusaelp ni tuo yrc uoY
,etisbew sih kcehc ro
no lleps a tup sah ohw uoy si tI
.merkE ,evah I ekil reffus ot uoy hsiw ton od I tub ,ecarbme ym htiw uoy dnib dluohs I fi derednow evah I
.uoy gnisol tuoba hcum os yrrow I yhw s'tI
.niaga yppah eb reven
.em dellarhtne sah ohw uoy ti fi ro
.ysatsce ni em rednu ehtirw uoy ,edisni tsurht I sA   .timbus
.erised dluoc xof a gnihtyreve evah I
.no dloh ot evah uoy sa
.spih ruoy revo depard liat ym
.llew os em daer uoY
.struh ti uoy rof yrgnuh oS .uoy rof yrgnuH
,uoy htiw tey dna ,sgniht eseht rof sgnol
.tey toN .yadot ton tuB
.em rof tog uoy stpircsunam dlo revo gnirop sruoh wef tsal eht tneps gnivah
.em evol uoy yhw rednow I taht ,pu flesym kcils I sa worg ot gnitrats tonk ym ,gninedrah flesym leef I sa ,tnemom taht ni si tI
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.eltsac siht ni
.evil nac ew yaw ylno eht si taht fi
.enoyna ot emoc mrah on ees ot hsiw I
nwad erofeb tsuj krad eht ni tnuh niaga lliw I
rettiwt no gnitirw sih tuoba erom dnif nac uoY
.uoy no lleps on tup
.lliw I ezilaer ot gninnigeb ma I dna
.deb siht ni em tsniaga mraw llits er'uoy elihw toN
ydob ym tsniaga ruf mraw ruoy dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb ”gnorW si uoY gnivoL“ saw sihT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.em gninokceb meht dna sserttam eht fo pot no gnitteg uoy hctaw I sa
daetsni uoY .em ekil retsnom a morf yawa nur dluow tsoM
goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ti noitnem reven uoy tub ,dloc ma I ,ereht nwod nevE
,raed ym uoy retne I nehw driew leef tsum tI
?merkE ,nialpmoc uoy t'nod yhW
.ydob etihw dna der ym tsniaga gnikcub ruf dettops ruoY
,reverof su dnib ot
,uoy dellarhtne evah I fi ton wonk I dna
,em sevird taht yppah uoy ees ot si tI
.tol a taht tuoba yrrow I
eeffochtiwflow@ ta
,taeH dna GNAF ekil seigolohtna ni deraeppa sah krow esohw
.ruf ruoy no llits ti fo stnih eht leef nac I
.eniwtretni ew elihw spsar eciov sselhtaerb ym neve dna
,rehtegot eb nac ew sa gnol sa
.ti rof kool I sa ,oot dnah no thgir syawla si ebul ehT
.deb eht ot em dael dna
repsihw ti ekam stsurht ym fo hcaE
.floW-pilS htiw slangiS tnedissiD ygolohtna eht detide ohw dna
,em evig lliw uoy gnihtyreve tnaw I
”gnorW si uoY gnivoL“
.niaga meht evah I
.uoy ot sdrow teews gnirepsihw ,elims I
.efil fo edahs elap a llits si rehtegot htaed ni ytinrete nA
,sluos evah llits seripmav eveileb ton od I
.uoy hguorht ecneirepxe ylno nac dna