tcefrep erew moor gnivil eht ni snoitaroced ehT
.gninrom samtsirhC no stneserp s’eno gninepo fo noitapicitna eht fo eno gnidnimer repap thgirb lufituaeb ni retnuoc eht nopu tas stneserp ekaF
,pihsdrah tuohtiw neeb ton dah doohdlihc s’ycuL dna sivaD elihW
,ylimaf a meht llac ton did yletarebiled etaK
uoy t’nerA“  .dias ehs ”,suoiciled oS“
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  sreviR neruaL yb
ohw ekanselttar kcabdnomaid a
.esrup reh ni dnuora hsif ot gnitrats ,dias ehs ”,tpiecer eht evah llits I esuaceB“
.eganam dluoc ehs elims gnirussaer tsom eht reh evag ycuL ,swap reh ni sdnah reh gnikaT  .reh ot saw taht suoicerp woh reve naht erom detaicerppa won ehs etaK tem gnivaH
.thgil hcrop eht rednu rehto hcae dleh yeht sa
”.elbuort tcartta ot mees htob uoy fo owt eht tuB“
,ffuts yadiloh siht ta tseb eht ton m’I wonk I“
.ycuL yb reh ot nevig saw hcihw fo tsom
.deksa ehs ”?xelA rof tiaw ew elihw ereh ni ezilaicos owt uoy t’nod yhw os ,ydaer s’rennid erofeb elihw a eb ll’tI  .doog ,lleW“
,god.ecioveht ta
..rekih-hctih flowerew
,ylthgils dexaler ehs eeffoc mraw reh fo pis a gnikaT  .denialpmoc etaK
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,cisum samtsirhC ot netsil ,slorac gnis ew ,lleW“ .deksa etaK ”?samtsirhC ta od uoy od esle tahw oS“
”!ecaps lanosrep ym no gnidurtni no
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
nwo ym etaerc nac I ssiM ,ereh tuo elbatrofmoc yats nac I yaw ylno eht s’tI
gib artxe erif eht tliub I
.llew dedne ton dah
.deilper etaK ”,hcuM“ ”?retteB“
.reh ediseb tas dna hcuoc eht ot pu deklaw rehtorb reh ,ycnednopsed reh gnicitoN
noitseuq eht deksa yllanif ycuL
,elzzum denrut nwod reh hguorht reh ta pu dekool ehS
,rood eht nepo dellup dna
.ecaf reh otni llaf ot tah retniw reh fo pot eht no llab foop elttil eht gniwolla
dna ereht llits saw dad ym nehw
”…od ot esle gnihtyna evah t’nod uoy fI
”,eivom yppas a er’uoy fI“
”.ereh ni ytsaot dna ecin ti peek yeht tsael tA“
.pis detapicitna yltoh taht gnikat erofeb sesnes reh llif ti gnittel
.tucriah retrohs a htiw dna redlo tahwemos
.eman s’etaK fo gnirettel eht revo dap wap reh nar ehs sregnif reh neewteb lairetam eht gnileeF
”.si esuoh s’mom ym erehw wonk uoy“ ,nageb ehs
,snoitaroced pu tup dluow spohS
.saet fo sexob eht raen detser taht haronem eht htiw gnola sllaw eht detaroced sthgil fo sgnirts lareveS
,eye reh thguac taht eeffoc eht ton saw ti tuB
mra eerf reh rednu seikooc fo xob eht pu dekcip ehs tellaw reh ot drac eht gninruteR
.nevo eht morf mraw llits dna
”,thgiR !HO“ .deksa etaK
”.ti ni stfig tup dna ecalperif eht revo ti gnah uoY
pihsnoitaler tsal reh nehw tnemtrapa na rof gnihcraes neeb dah ycuL ,ecnedicnioc fo eno neeb dah gniteem tsrif riehT
”?em deen uoy od ,yrros m’I“
s’ekanselttar eht tsniaga elzzum reh gnitnalp ,reh ssik ot drawrof dehsur ycuL hsinif ot reh rof gnitiaw toN
.ssensuoiciled gniretawhtuom htiw mirb eht ot dellif yalpsid ssalg eht ta detniop ehS
.erofeb ylimaf a dah reven ev’I
”,flesym uoy mraw ot evah tsuj ll’I sseug I neht lleW“  .deggurhs ycuL
.redluohs reh dnuora mra sih depparw eh ,elims gnirussaer tsom sih gnireffO
.gnikcots a s’tI“ .deksa etaK
,sehtolc fo ecnadnuba na gniraew rof eno ton saw yllamron
”?mraw s’ti erehw edisni og esaelp ew nac
rehtom evitroppus a dah syawla dah ehs
rehtom sih gniwollof erofeb
ehs litnu tae reh ekam ot gniog s’mom woN
,wonk ot dedeen ehs lla ycuL dlot dah don eltbus tahT
”,siht ekil nosaes a syojne enoyna woh wonk t’nod I“
daeh reh derewol ehs esuoh s’rehtom reh sdrawot ylwols gnigdurT
,rennid gib a sekam moM
.eromyna seikooc eht llems neve ton dluoc ehS
.wons eht otni tuo kcab gniklaw erofeb redluohs reh dezeeuqs ycuL sa gnihton dias etaK
.reh dnuora smra reh parw dna tuo hcaer ot ycuL gnitpmorp
.delims dna sdnah reh no ti dleh etaK
dnuor meht fo hcae
llits s’ereht fi thguoht I tub
.teerts eht ssorca pohs eeffoc etirovaf reh ot yaw reh edam ehs sa ecaf reh ssorca tperc elims A
.gniws lluf ni nosaes eht fo erutan evitsef eht htiw ,tnereffid on saw pohs eeffoc eht fo edisni ehT
.ydob reh no erow ehs sehtolc eht naht rehto eman reh ot elttil dah dna ,gnol yrev rof erehwyna deyats reven ehS
.denrecnoc ylsuoivbo ,dias eh
”.raey siht su nioj ot etaK teg dluoc I taht gnipoh saw tsuj I“
,elbat eeffoc eht no puc a dellif senac ydnaC
.mrof lacisyhp rieht naht rehtar edisni eht no ekil saw nosrep a tahw ni detseretni erom neeb syawla dah ehS
.esuoh siht ni mraw ytnelp s’ti ,uoy esimorp I ,taoc ruoy em eviG“
”?thgir tae t’nod sdik uoy tluaf ym ti sI“ ”.stsrub
.dednetni ylbaborp ehs naht reduol tib a ,dias etaK
.gnihtemos gniyas
,deb reh ni sthgin wef a naht erom tneps gnivah ,ti eciton dluow eno on yldrawtuo elihW
etaK ta revo ecnalg a tsac ehs ,drac tibed reh
,eye reh hctac ot deirt ehs ,gnilimS
rehtegot tae lla ew dna
traeh doog tub degamad a htiw
.emoh gnivol a dna
seikooc fo xob eht pu gnikciP
,tnereffid yrev neeb dah gnignirbpu s’etaK ,ycuL ekilnU
,gnihtyna fo diarfa ton saw ohw ,etaK
reh edisni ycuL revarb ,regnorts a nees dah nrut ni ehS
.egaP ytiniffaruF 'soidutS ecnecsedirI no
etaK taht thguoht eht ta pu gniraet seye reh tlef ehs ,tcejbo
,soidutS ecnecsedirI yb nooM eulB fo rohtuA
.deddon haraS  .dias ehs
.’dneirflrig s’retsis ym‘ sa reh ot refer ot emoc neve dah
.yllaer ton ,reh rof derac reven dah rehtom reh sa
,selknirps neerg dna der ni derevoC
.snoitasnes reh llud ot demees
,reh tuohtiw emas eht ton saw efil taht dnuof dah ehs yaw eht gnola erehwemos tuB
.dias ehs ”,ycuL“  .etaK saw
.nevo eht fo tuo gnimoc seikooc dekab ylhserf fo llems eht yb detcartsid emaceb ehs sa
.deksa eh ”?yeht t’nod ,samtsirhC dnuora neppah syawla selcariM“
,onicupparf emèrc etalocohc etihw A“  .deksa eh
noitangidni laicos reh tub ,samtsirhC fo rovaf ni degnahc trohs tog syawla hakkunaH taht riafnu yldlim demees ti woh desum ycuL
.derevocsid d’ehs os ro ,evol saw evoL
”,meht no eman ym evah meht fo emoS“
.snoitnetni doog htiw neve ,reh ot emas eht od ot desufer ehs dna
.rekih-hctih flowerew
,ees ot lla rof pot pu denihs rats wolley thgirb A
,tnelis werg etaK .deksa ehs
.syadiloh etarbelec t’ndid ew yawa em koot mom ecnO“
”,hctab a dehsinif tsuj ew ,gnimit doog tog ev’uoY“
.raey fo emit siht ta slleb raluger eht decalper syawla taht slleb elgnij erutangis eht gnireggirt
.tnemetatsrednu na neeb dah suoutlumut neeb dah yenruoj rieht
.noitome fo yalpsid eht ta dessarrabme ylraelc
tahW“  .unem eht desurep ehs sa evaw a htiw atsirab eht deteerg dna taoc reh deppiznu sseflow ednolb ehT  .retnuoc eht ot pu deklaw ehs ,elims thgirb a htiW
.deddon ycuL ,detnioppasiD
”.sllor esruoc fo dna ,puos nekcihc
”,ycuL ,samtsirhC yrreM“
’em pleh‘ gnihtuom
,sesimerp eht no edaM
.ti nopu gnikcots reh gnicalp
,ti tuoba kniht ot emit dedeen uoy dias uoy taht wonk I“
.noitcefrep ot dekab
”.yadot hcum netae yllaer t’nevah I“  .dettimda etaK
.nageb ehs ”,…em rof moor
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dnalrednow retniw elbatirev a otni demrofsnart devil ehs hcihw ni ecalp eht ,wons ni deteknalB  .raey fo emit etirovaf s’ycuL syawla erew syadiloh ehT
,ti no ogol s’pohs eeffoc eht htiw xob eht delbmessa yldipar eh reh sdrawot ti gnidilS
.teef reh ta derats dna nwod dekool etaK .deilper ehs
.rehtorb reh ot denrut dna dehgis ehs ,os od ot deliaf ehs nehW
.teerts eht nwod yaw reh edam ehs sa
tub ycuL ot ralimis rehtar gnikool rehtom reh ,emit emas eht ta tuo emac rehtorb dna rehtom reH
.walc reh pu dleh neht enaKcM redle ehT
,eelg yadiloh htiw swodniw sti derevoc dah pohs yreve tsoM
,ti ekil t’nod I taht ti ton s’tI“
.rehto eht ro yaw eno reh ot derettam reve dah ti ekil ton
,sretaews yllis raew dluow elpoep
devol ehs nosrep eht tuohtiw yadiloh eht gnidneps fo aedi eht wohemos tub ,deretne d’ehs nehw morf degnahc dah gnihtoN
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”,yllautca ,devratS“
.thgiarts flesreh deredisnoc dah ehs
.egats retnec gnikat eert samtsirhC eht htiw ,syawla sa
deifingid a gniniatniam llits elihw
elbat eht ta detiaw ehs ,sdnah reh ni eeffoc fo puc mraw a htiW
.ti mialc ot ereh eb ton dluow
,sreviR neruaL yb
.delims ycuL  ”.od yeht esruoc fo ,lleW“ .dias ehs
”.enaKcM .srM ,uoy knahT“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,neppah dluow ti niatrec saw ehs ekil
yas oT  .reh ot tnaem ehs hcum woh dezilaer ehs nehw ekauqhtrae na fo tib a neeb dah ti lrig thgiarts desseforp fles a sa tub
”,dnim ruoy egnahc uoy fI“
.uoy ees ot evol yllaer dluow mom ym dna doof hcum os evah syawla ew tuB“
.pu smlap sih dleh sivaD  .deilper ehs
”?os yas tsuj uoy t’ndid yhw ti ekil t’ndid uoy fI“ ”!tah diputS“
.neeb dah elyoC nitneuQ ot egairram reh noc gnol eht nur ot ecalp tsrif eht ni reh dah ylno dah rehtom reh
”.etaK ,samtsirhC yrreM“  .delims ehs
,tah eht gnitator yltneG .delims ycuL
”,samtsirhC laer a dah reven ev’I wonk uoY“
”.esuoh yalp ot gniyrt llits saw ettelociN
,seotatop dehsam ,ecuas yrrebnarc
”?ti si tahW“ ”.uoy rof si sihT“
.ti fo edisni namow eht rehtar tub
— floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.puc eht fo htmraw eht morf sdnah reh devom ton dah raf os taht elitper eht ta gnilims ,deksa ehs ”?hguone mraW“
”.em ot tol a snaem taht dna uoy morf s’tI
.reh ediseb gnittis ,reh ot ti dednah dna gnikcots eht pu dekcip ehs ,hcuoc eht ot reh gnidiuG ”.sevruc eht dnuora uoy reets ll’I“
”.niaga enola eb ot gniog reven er’uoy dnA“  .dias ehs
.s’ycuL no dnah reh gnicalp ,dias etaK ”!ON“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?taht lla ni mraw
.elbat eht fo retnec eht ni esuoh yrtnuoc gnimrahc a gnirutaef ebolgwons a htiw hcuoc eht denil reednier dna atnaS htiw snoihsuC
,samtsirhC dnuora tsuj ton dna ,taht fo erom esu dluoc dlrow eht thguoht syawla ehS
mih gnidnaH  .dias eh ”,62.81$ eb ll’tahT  .og uoy erehT“
.erehwyreve sualC atnaS fo segami dna
.daeh s’etaK fo edis eht no ylmlac detser ffup redwop eht taht os ti denrut ehs
.seitivitsef yadiloh eht diova ot redro ni detsisni dah ehs taht niatrec
”hsiW samtsirhC s’ycuL“
thgirb ssel elttil a demees snoitaroced eht ,deretne ehs nehw ekilnU
elbissop sa hcum sa pu delruc
.ti ot deerga reven dah ehs ssenriaf ni hguoht
”,ekil uoy fi ,pu ti nrut ot meht ksa nac I“
naeb eeffoc a htiw ettal tcefrep a
.nwonk reve dah ehs enoyna naht erom raf
”.samtsirhC no tneserp a steg enoyrevE“
.swap reh ni gnikcots eht tlef niaga ycuL ,enola reh gnivaeL
.ssik rehtona ycuL evag etaK ,tsal ta enolA
”.gnihtyreve fo erac ekat ll’I  .ereh thgir yats uoY“
.reehc yadiloh lausu reh nommus ot drah ti dnuof ycuL ,moor gnivil ylimaf enaKcM eht ni detaeS
,ees ot lla rof eveels reh no traeh reh erow ycuL elihW
,tnemom siht yojne ot tnaw yllaer I sa hcum sA“
rehto eht htiw knird reh pu depoocs ehs ,elbat eht morf
.rehto ro gnihtemos fo puc gnimaets a ni deirub ecaf reh dah llits ohw
.wap eno htiw kcab eht no taoc reh gnicalp
.deggurhs eH  ”.evE samtsirhC s’ti ,lla retfA“
,rehtorb reh ,ycuL rof eno
stnemanro ssalg lufituaeb ni derevoc eert samtsirhC egral a saw wodniw eht yb renroc eht nI
ycuL# ”.thginot rab eht krow ot em deksa laS“  .deilper etaK
”.yrgnuh er’uoy epoh I“
.revol enipul reh ta tuo eugnot dekrof reh gnikcits ,deilper etaK ”,taeh ydob
.rettam eht no dias eb ot dedeen taht erom gnihton saw ereht
.noitisop emas eht ot nruter ot ti rof ylno
.snoitaraperp yadiloh erom sdrawot
.gnihtolc retniw fo sreyal wef a etiuq ni flesreh revoc ot nesohc dah yadot tub
”.yrrow t’nod tub ,samtsirhC ylimaf enaKcM a ssel hcum ,erofeb samtsirhC laer a dah reven ev’uoy wonk I woN“
”.ylimaf a gnivah ot desu teg dluoc I“
.seiceps ro redneg htiw od ot gnihton dah pihsnoitaler a ni sgniht tnatropmi eht taht saw taht lla morf denrael ehs gnihtemos teY
.dias ycuL ”,tcefreP“
.swap reh ni gnikcots eht revoc ot deirt dna delahxe ycuL
,elzzum reh derewol etaK  ”.eno laer a toN
,xob eht ni seikooc tcefrep eht fo ruof ytnewt decalp eh sa dehctaw ycuL  .maof eht fo tuo edam
,neddih snoitome reh tpek etaK
.gnigaruocne eb ot gniyrt ,dias eh
.elbisiv tsom saw ti nehw raey fo emit eht saw ti tub
.ti rewsna ot dniheb gnikcots eht tfel ehs ,hcuoc eht morf pu gnitteG
,wot ni sivaD htiw nehctik eht otni gniklaw ,delkcuhc ehS
…tsuj I  .erofeb tuoba yrros m’I“
”!ereh s’etaK ,sivaD ,moM“
.deddon ycuL ,desirprus toN .dias etaK
”.esaelp ,seikooc esoht fo redro na dnA  .ednarg
.yaw taht ti peek ot nalp I dna ,seY“
,tser eht htiw pu gnikcots s’dad tuohtiw samtsirhC ton saw ti dias dah ycuL gnuoy tub
.dias etaK ”,nuf evaH“
.eson reh no ssik a detnalp ehS
.egareveb mraw reh gnippis ,dias ehs ”,sknaht oN
.reh rof taht detnaw ehs ,gnitad erew yeht taht degdelwonkca yllanif dah ycuL dna etaK taht woN  .ylimaf laer a htiw nosaes yadiloh eht fo yoj eht ecneirepxe ot teg dluohs enoyreve taht dna
,ti gniriter tuoba deklat dah yehT
.deerga yldetraehelohw dah rehtom reh dna
taht etaK ni kraps a ees ot emoc dah ycuL emit ni tub ,tsael eht yas ot ecneirepxe gninrael a erew syad wef tsrif riehT
.retal tnemom a denruter dna moordeb eht ni ffo sgniht s’etaK pord ot denrut ehS
.taoc retniw reh erow llits etaK gniciton ,deksa ehs
.esahcrup reh rof ngis ot detpmorp saw ehs os od dluoc ehs erofeb tub
ecaf reh no selacs egieb dna nworb reh ezingocer llits dluoc ehs ,desserdrevo yllacitsiretcarahcnU
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,tah eht rof niaga uoy knaht dnA“
yltcefrep syawla erew seikooc eht
,elyoC etaK eno saw wodniw eht nihtiw yltcefrep demarF
snoitanihcam s’rehtom reh yb erugif tnesba na neeb gnivah rehtaf reh htiw
”.wonk mom tel ll’I“  .dias ehs ”,yakO“
.lamron raeppa ot tseb reh did ycuL
efil elohw reh enod dah ettelociN gnihtemos saw reh gnihsuP
,eltnam eht ssorca gnuh sgnikcots ruoF
.delleuq eb ot desufer yletulosba
.esrow sgniht ekam ylno dluow
.sevlesmeht rof detnaw elpoep tsom efil tcefrep erutcip eht yldrah saw doohdlihc s’etaK ,hcus sA
.edis rehto eht ot revo kcab dils dna keehc reh dessik ycuL ,dnah reh gnibbuR
.trats ot ,ynapmoc s’rehto hcae yojne tsuj yllareneg dna
.mottob ot pot morf sthgil deroloc dna
— floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
”.uoy rof moor syawla s’erehT“
,noitatibahoc lautum rieht gnirud denrael dah ehs tahw dnoyeb tsap reh tuoba hcum deklat ton dah ekanselttar ehT
.gnignah ydaerla ruof eht ot detniop ycuL
,riahc reh otni delttes ehs egareveb reh fo pis a gnikaT  .dias ehs ”,yakO“
.tnelis deniamer ycuL
”,nac uoy elihw nuR  .demood er’uoY“
emoh ta dekan dnuora deklaw ohw rednetrab ekans suoiretsym eht fo ekam ot tahw nwonk ton dah ycuL tem tsrif dah yeht nehW
”.em rof gnitiaw era sivaD dna moM
.nirg suoveihcsim a htiw ecnalg s’etaK tem ehs ,elbat eht fo edis rehto eht ot revo seikooc eht gnidilS
”?ereh ni wap a teg I nac ,yeH“
.roolf eht no reh nioj ot revo deklaw ehS
.nehctik eht ot tuo dellac ycuL ,dekcol rood eht htiW
,gnuoy saw I nehw meht dah eW“ ”.detcepsus I“
,oitar eno ot owt tcefrep eht ni syawla saw ti ,sthgil etihw dna deroloc ni derevoC
”…dna ,tes ot setalp ynam woh wonk ot sdeen mom tub
gnol tsal ton did
rehtorb dna rehtom reh ot esimorp reh ot eud ylno saw ti ,meht gnitae ni detseretni regnol oN
.hcneb tseraen eht no meht gnippord morf reh tpek taht meht gnirb d’ehs taht
saw sihT        .deilper etaK
,gninepo eht gnieeS
.rehtegot samtsirhC a tneps reven dah yeht hguoht neve ,syadiloh eht erew oot os dna
”.ylimaf ruo fo trap er’uoy snaem tahT“
ylpmis erew rethguad dna dnabsuh reh rof noitome reh llA
,tseb yadiloh reh fo lla ni depparw edis rehto eht no gnidnatS
ytniatrec eht saw esoht fo eno dna traeh reh ot esolc sgniht niatrec dleh ehs tuB
,loraC samtsirhC a gnis ro
.tfig a sa reh ot ti nevig gnivah ,deksa ycuL
,gnisserd emos ,yekrut a edam I“  .deksa ehs
.retsis dna rehtom sih morf kcams a mih gninrae tnemmoc eht ,dias sivaD
,sgniht emas eht od enoyreve did ron ,samtsirhC detarbelec enoyreve ton taht wenk ehS
.nosaes yadiloh yna fo thgilhgih eht syawla erew yeht
enac ydnac a tae reh nees reven dah ehS
.syadiloh eht dnuora did elpoep tsom taht sgniht fo rebmun yna ro
”,gninrom eht ni stneserp eht gninepo dna thgin eht gnidneps erofeb
.tah retniw reh htaenrednu riah htgnel redluohs nworb reh sa llew sa
.reh ediseb gnizeeuqs dna edis rehto eht ot dnuora gnimoc ,dias ehs
.laeh ot gninnigeb won ylno saw ycuL hcihw
”,em rof evah uoy revetahw tae ot yppah m’I“  .delims etaK
eht dnoyeb ,yrotsih reh dniheb hturt lluf eht ycuL llet ot tnatiseh demees
.eirever reh morf reh koohs llebrood eht fo gnir neddus eht ,desolc seye reH
.egareveb reh ta nwod gnikool
.deffocs ehs ,smra reh ni meht gnikaT
t’nsaw etaK nehw llet dluoc ehs
.rednik tib elttil a eb ot yaw rieht fo tuo og ot demees tsuj enoyreve dna
neht devorppa rehtorb reh fi sa
puc yadiloh etairporppa yllanosaes a ni
”.evif saw I ecnis eert samtsirhC a dah neve ev’I kniht t’nod I
,sreviR neruaL yb
.pordkcab der eht tsniaga sekalfwons fo noitidner a ni derevoc
”,gnimoc t’nerew uoy thguoht I“
ti no reh gnillac tub ,krow ot etaK deksa ton dah laS wenk ehs ekanselttar eht gnihctaW
”,ti ekam nac I kniht t’nod I“
ni dnah edis rehto eht tuo emoc dah yeht wohemos teY
.noitcafsitas fo hgis a desaeler ehs eugnot reh taoc egareveb looc eht gnileeF
degreme dah etaK taht fo lla hguorht wohemos teY  .snoc reh ni nwap a sa tenalp eht no nosrep rehto yreve was ohw namow a yb desiar neeb gnivah flesreh dna
.dias haraS ”,elbuort eb ot si sekil
daor eht dessorc ycuL ,desumA
.gnilkcuhc tsiser ton dluoc lerriuqs eht esuaceb ,tib elttil a deloord evah tsum ehS
.ti nruter ot tnaw t’nod I“
,elitper a saw dneirflrig reh taht rednimer eht ta ylthgils delkcuhc ycuL
.erif tliub llew a htiw yawa delkcarc hcihw ,ecalperif eht ediseb tas namwons nedoow a dna
.edisni emoc ot reh gniwolla kcab gnippets ,dias ycuL
.deggurhs ehs ,taefed ot dengiseR
.ti no eman s’etaK htiw derediorbme ,swap reh ni gnikcots htfif a dleh ycuL
,gnihctah reh fo tnemom eht morf reh devol dah rehtaf
,ebordraw retniw reh gniraew naht rehto yaw yna ni
,seye reh morf erutsiom eht gnipiW ”.sis ,yeH“
”.tressed rof moor evas dna ,hO“
,etalocohc etihw fo amora eht delahni ehs eson reh ot pu puc reh gnitfiL
”.ti ekil od yllaer I
,noitseuq eht gnidiova neeb dah ekanselttar ehT
,ragus fo sebuc deroloc elttil ekil dekool taht dnik eht
”.retal rof era esehT“
,wap reh ni dnah reh gnikaT  ”.rof ksa dluoc I tfig tseb eht si ereh gnieb er’uoY“  .dias ycuL ”,eergasid I ,hO“  .deilper etaK
.tol a dnuora devom dah etaK wenk sseflow eht ,tem dah yeht erofeB
.esab sti dnuora selcric sseldne ni gniog tes niart ynit a htiw
.s’rehtom reh ot revo emos gnikat dna
ecnadnetta s’etaK fo nekops dah ehs thgirtuo ti dias ton dah ehs hguohT
.taht dias evah t’ndluohs ehS“
.ekanselttar kcabdnomaid eht nioj ot revo deklaw dna
”,won eno tog ev’uoy ,lleW“
meht degdelwonkca ton ylpmis dah etaK ,llet dluoc ehs sa raf sA
evitsef eht ta nwod gniratS
.dias eh ”,mom gnimoC“
.gnimoc saw lufrednow gnihtemos ekil leef sseflow yarg eht edam syawla meht gnieeS
.rehtegot gnivil erew yeht wenk ehs gniht txen eht dna ,flesreh etammoor a tsol tsuj gnivah ,dereffo dah etaK
.ycuL ta gnikool ,ecaf a edam sivaD
,samtsirhC no enola eb dluohs eno on taht
.gniog teg ot tog ev’I“
”.citnamor a m’I ,yeH“
*	      *	      *	                                                                .hsart eht otni llaf puc reh tel dna
,eil a saw taht wenk
.dehsulb dna eert eht erofeb tlenk etaK  .dias ehs
.rehtaf etal reh dna ,rehtom reh
”?uoy rof teg I nac
gnitsisni speek ti taht tcaf eht s’ti
”?yawyna lrig taht si erehW“
.hcuoc eht sdrawot reh gnidiug dna reh dnuora mra reh gnipparw
dah ohw ,rehtorb reh dna ,evitroppus naht erom neeb dah rehtom reh ,os nevE
”?evE samtsirhC rof thginot s’rehtom ym ot gnimoc uoy erA“
,yawa ti dettab ehs ytingidni eht yb detlusnI
.sliated ronim ylno saw ti neht neve dna
.desuap ehS  ”.wonk I“
saw tI  .tuo emoc ot gniggeb tsuj
.swap reh tuo dleh dna rehto tnacifingis s’rethguad reh ta ylmraw delims enaKcM haraS
”hsiW samtsirhC s’ycuL“   yojne esaelP
.namow regnorts a xe reh fo egakcerw eht fo tuo emoc dah ehs etaK fo esuaceb
egareveb suoiciled eht gniraperp ,knird eht dexim eh tsriF  .redro reh llifluf ot gnivom ,dias eh
?nwod ti nrut ot em ta gnilley ereh ni doolbmraw yreve evah dnA“ .dereffo ycuL
,revol dedoolb dloc reh no ytip gnikaT
,etaK rof sgnileef reh reggirt ot deneppah dah tahw erus ton saw ehS
.tnereffid saw ti etaK rof tuB
meht fo etalp a gniyub tsiser reven  dluoc ehs
,ylmraw delims ehS
.detnarg rof ekat ot demees ycuL snoitidart yadiloh lausu eht fo yna ni gnitapicitrap yllaer ton
ehs tahW“ .deilper sivaD ”,ecnartne na ekam ot sekil ehs wonk uoy ,moM“
.nosaes eht rof ssenregae lausu reh erotser dluow ti taht sepoh eht ni snoitaroced yadiloh eht ta gnirats ,ereht deniamer dna hcuoc eht no tas dah ehs seikooc eht ffo gnippord dna edisni gnimoc retfA
.aera nwotnwod eht dnuora os yllaicepse saw sihT
senac ydnac dna shtaerw htiw
.meht ot dellac dna tuo daeh reh dekop rehtom rieht ,nehctik eht morF
.snoitom eht hguorht og ot tnaw ot syadiloh eht htiw detaicossa niap hcum oot dah ylpmis emos dna
”.haraS em llac ,uoy dlot I“
”,gnihtyna uoy teg t’ndid I“
.sgniht yzarc od ot reh degaruocne dna
,etaK ot roirp woh fo reh dednimer tI
”hsiW samtsirhC s'ycuL“
.rehtom s’ycuL ot ffo meht dednah ehs sa stekcop eht edisni sevolg eht gnikcut ,taoc dna tah reh dehs etaK  ”.uoy rof tsuj
.noitisop detaes
.tfig a sa reh ot ti tneserp ot dennalp dah ehS
.ekans eht ta erom ecno dekool dna
.og tel ot detnaw reven ehs niatrec ycuL htiw ,dnah
reh saerehW  .nalp reh ot stnemele
.skeew rof ksa ot gnitiaw neeb dah ehs
.ti otni reh decrof yltnetrevdani ton dah ehs fi reh dlot evah ton thgim ehs taht neve dna ,cisab
.sraet lufyoj htiw tew erew seye reh yawa dellup yllanif ycuL nehw ,reverof ekil demees tahw rof ti gnidloH
pihsnoitaler lairasrevda tahwemos laitini rieht retfa reh tsurt ot emoc
.efil fo tcaf a ylpmis saw tI  .sterces dah enoyreve wenk ycuL
,gnitiaw dna ydaer kooh a gnidnif ,doots ehS
.deksa eh ”?yako gnihtyrevE“
”,ylrae s’ti ,thgim llits ehS“
.roolf eht gnola snoitulover lauteprep gnikam
”,em deen thgim uoy gnikniht yllautca saw I“ .deksa ehs
.od ot boj rehtona ,nur ot noc rehtona syawla saw erehT
tes niart euqitna s’dad reh htiw
,rebmeceD fo htnom eht gnirud ereh gnimoc deyojne syawla ehs snosaer eerht eht fo enO