.worg ot gnitrats tonk nwo sih gnileef
,esnopser ni ylduol denaom tsuj etammoor siH .detnap oeL
,ffo dekcals gnikorts siH
,elbat eht revo denael xof ehT
.oeL denihw ”,gib oot s’tI“
,denihw lakcaj ehT ”.tonk eht ot tsuJ“
,lakcaj eht dias ”,ereh thgiR“
”.…stonk cilrag gnirb did uoy tub ,eurT“
”.deticxe em sekam stonk tuoba deticxe gnieb uoY“ .keehc ot keehc
.ylluferac mih dedrager xof ehT
”.oot nac uoy ,siht od nac I fI
,xelA detnap ”,nooS“
”.yxof ,thginot toN“
,setalp gnikcol htiw meht lles yehT“
.elttil a derewol srae s’lakcaj ehT
.won ,woN“ ”.doof dna xeS“
.krow ot gniog saw siht fi tey tuo eninac eht tel t’ndluoc eh ,yawynA
,doof ym etsat ot tnaw I esuaceb egatnavda etelpmoc a htiw uoy sevael llits tI“
.daeh sih detlit dna desuap eH
yot eht detlih d’eH
.ni gnippils yllanif ti
.uoy tespu ot tnaw t’nod I .yrros m’I ,kooL“ .dehgis oeL
.xof eht morf yawa retnuoc eht no doof eht gnittup ,lakcaj eht deksa
.xof eht ot revo deklaw dna
.yrruh retteb uoy os pu dekrow elttil a llits er’uoy dnA
.xof eht dias ”!doof s’ti ,eduD“
,yob fo epyt taht ton m’I dneterp dluoc I
?elbat eht fO“ .deknilb oeL
.mih fo tuo deppils lakcaj eht sa ,xelA dias ”,siht tog I“
,dias xof eht ,htuom sih fo tuo gnillor eugnoT
.ssa s’lakcaj eht tsniaga yot eht sserp ot detrats eh dna ,xof eht dias
”?yas uoy nalp A“
,xof eht dias ”,hcum oot s’ti fi wonk em teL“
,xof eht dias ”,em no sucoF“
”.em no dellup uoy kcirt ebuc eci eht nettogrof t’nevah llits I“
.psarg s’lakcaj eht ni denihw xof ehT
”.yldneirf era sruoy fo emos tsael tA
”.elbat eht gnikcil detrats dna…“
trihs krow s’oeL ta deggut wap A
lwob gnixim eht ot txen knis eht otni nac eht dessot eh ,flesmih ta dessiP
,stonk ruoy tae nac uoY
?nuf si enohp eht no yad lla sremotsuc etari htiw gnilaed kniht uoY
,no desserp lakcaj ehT
deen uoY“ .ylreporp flesmih noitisop ot deirt dna
,ti no sgnikram on dah tI
.seye sih dellor xelA
”.wonk uoy ,egnellahc a ekil I“
.tcepsni ot xelA rof pu dleh eh hcihw odlid a tuo dellup dna
”.thginot laro naht snoitnetni rehto dah uoy gnikniht m’I ,eseht htiw tub
”.gniod m’I tahw wonk I“
.dehguoc neht dna deknilb
sdnab eht rof sretsop htiw deb neeuq a elihw
.muc d’eh sa oeL fo edisni thgir
?nruter ni ksa ti seod tahw dna ,evil ot droffa nac ew os ti od ew
.kcab tnew srae s’lakcaj ehT ”.od uoy“
,kooL“ .dehgis lakcaj ehT
reward eht otni dehcaer eh sa
.xelA ot meht gnidnah dna
.lakcaj eht ot deit llits ,thgiew sih detfihs xelA sa tuhs dewercs seye s’oeL ”…tsuj eW“
,dnuorg eht tih ti erofeb ti hctac ot deganam eH
.pit evitisnes sih ssorca dap s’oeL fo eparcs wols eht ta delworg xelA
deb eht no tog xof ehT
”.enod er’ew nehw gnihtemos ro hcuoc eht no hsarc og ylbaborp lliw I dna tae s’teL
”.evisausrep eb nac I“
,kroW“ .dehgis lakcaj ehT
,oeL dias ”,tnaw uoy emityna flesruoy esaeler nac uoY“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.moordeb ym ni uoy rof esirprus a tog ev’I ,no
,sdoow eht ot ffo nur dna dniheb dlrow nredom eht evael ot tnaw elpoep emos wonk I
.hctorc s’oeL ssorca wap toof sih deggard eh sa ,dias eh ”?ti eldnah nac uoy erus toN
.dekrep srae s’xof ehT
.ruf tsehc sih no ecuas emos gnibbur neht dna
”,nuf gnihtemos ,eruS“ ”?regaw A“
?yxof rettam eht s’tahW“ .dennirg oeL
.hcamots s’lakcaj eht no ssem eht ot dda ot hguone tub ,ylgnorts sa ton emit siht
”.won ’,ni ti evohs ,stif ti fi‘ ,tsuj lla ton m’I ,yeH“
.ecno ta eldnah nac hcae ew stonk ynam woh ees s’teL
.ecafrus nedoow s’elbat eht ssorca dekael dah stnetnoc s’nac eht fo tsom erofeb ton tub
”,hguoht ylenol si enola gniviL“
”.won thgin yreve kooc t’nac I
.tonk sti htiw yot eninac eht ta gnikool ,xof eht dias
”.taht t’nsaw tI !oN“ ”?won
.gniliec eht drawot tniop ot elzzum sih desiar yltnatsni ohw
”.ees I ,stcennocsid parts retnec ehT“
.toof sih deppord oeL
.dees pu-tnep sih desaeler lakcaj eht ,mih fo edisni elihw
,no emoC“ .spih sih detfihs xof ehT
”,hguoht nuf si siht ,ti nmaD“
”.emit emos sekat ti erus m’I“
.kcoc s’xof eht ta gniggut tpek tsuj dna
?detnioppasid os kool uoy od yhW“
,od ot tnaw ew sgniht eht od dna eriter ot droffa nac ew ,ykcul er’ew fI
.deb eht tsniaga depmuht ,mih rednu dennip saw hcihw
”?txen tog s’ohw rof regaw a tuoba woh tub ,dluohs eW“
tonk drah eht dezeeuqs oeL
.enola yot eht evael dna
.nac ytpme eht pu dekcip lakcaj ehT ”?thgiR“
rof yap ot denimreted taht er’uoy fI“
, gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
,snoitom cimhtyhr ni tfahs s’lakcaj eht krow ot gniyrt saw xelA
.ediw tnew seye sih neht dna
noitisop a ni sevles deit rieht tog yeht
.boj eht dehsinif eh os
”?eciuj elppaenip gniknird era uoy nosaer a ereht sI“
.ylhsipeehs deddon lakcaj ehT
sgnir eht fo eno no parts eht dekcilc eh ”,eurt s’tahT“
”tiF ti gnikaM“   yojne esaelP
,’ti kcuf‘ fo tnemom a nI
.yltneg kcen sih ta delbbin neht dna dekcil oeL
”?uoy rof gnitcartsid oot ti si ,tahW“
,tiaW“ .demialcxe eh
deb eht nwod detoocs eH
.psag xof eht gnikam
,oeL dias ”,won esrow siht ekam yllaer nac I …hhO“
”?yawyna ecno ta eldnah nac uoy kniht uoy od eseht fo ynam woH“
moor eht fo edis eno no tas tesdaeh a htiw retupmoc potksed A
.tsehc sih ta nwod dekool eH ”?od I“
”.neht laed riaf a t’nsaw taht sseug I“
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.hcamots sih evoba taolf rebmem ffits sih gnittel
,etammoor sih fo pot no kcuts saw xelA
.ti revo gnuh lwohthgiN dna xoB regnaD
,thginot azzip egasuas redro t’ndid eW“
.parts gnitcennoc eht gnidloh wap eht pu detfil dna
”.sffucdnah gniraew eno eht era uoy tub ,eb dluow tI“
,htaerb sih thguac eh retfa ,yllaniF
”!gnitaehc s’tahT“
sgel sih no sdnah sih tser
.dneirf sih edisni eit eht gnidnirg
.meht gniodnu dna sffuc eht htiw gnitegdif yllanif ,dias eh
”?uoy rof hguone t’nsi sihT“
kniht I ,haeY“ ”?htnom tsal neppah taht t’ndiD“
…mmH“ .naelc elzzum sih dekcil lakcaj eht
lakcaj eht fo ffo flesmih dellup xof eht ,ylderiT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.deb eht fo edis eht ot detfihs eh
kcab sih dniheb deniartser won erew sdnah siH .deggut dna
”.niw uoy ,yako ,yakO“
”.semitemos llew siht em wonk uoy etah I“
,ssenderit eht tub ,uoy toN“
”.lla ta gnignellahc mees t’nseod tahT“ ”.txen tog ev’I
esnopser ni elzzum sih otni tonk cilrag netae-flah sih fo tser eht deppop tsuj xelA
”?gnihtemos tegrof uoY“
.uoy rof eno tog ev’I ,tahw uoy lleT“
.atsap fo reniatnoc sih denepo tsuj dah lakcaj ehT
,ydob sih dnuora sdnah sih llup ot deirt dna denihw xelA
,enola devil I fi
”.egatnavdasid a ta uoy evah I eveileb I“
”.txen steg resol ehT .sniw
”.edisa eciuj elppaenip ,hu
.flesmih revo xof eht noitisop dluoc eh os elttil a tsuj
.rewol devom dna nottub pot eht didnu tigid a sa
.deffuh lakcaj ehT
ydeen leef I nehw taht rof yot a tog I tub ,ebyaM“
”.gniog era swalc esoht erehw hctaW !yeh yeH“
”.evitresni …erom gnihtemoS
.snoitazilivic tneicna
lakcaj dekcab-kcalb ehT
.nwod denael dna og tel eH
”.dnim I gnikooc ruoy ton s’tI“
”?no meht yrt ot tnaw uoy oD“ ”…on ,yltcaxe toN“
.noitautis eht fo lortnoc gnisol ylkciuq saw eh tub
,wap s’lakcaj eht otni tsurht ot gniyrt ,xof eht detnap ”,seY“
tfahs sih ot denruter wap s’oeL
.pu doots eh sa ffo ti yalp ot gniyrt ,dias xelA
,won htaehs sih fo tuo ylluf saw tfahs s’xelA
,etib rehtona ekat ot tnew xelA
”.ekam ew tahw ffo nwo ruo no tuo evom ot droffa nac su fo rehtien tub
”.thgin tsal taht dias uoY“
”.stonk eht otni egasuas ruoy pid uoy ees ot tnaw t’nod I“
knis eht ot revo tnew eH .oeL delbmum
,rae sih ni repsihw dluoc eh os tsehc s’xof eht pu elzzum sih deliart eh sa delkcuhc lakcaj ehT ”.desirprus tsuJ“
.gniggaw liat sih
.ssalg sih ni dednal dah eciuj fo pord a ton ,esroW
.pu kcab neht dna ,nwod neht dna
”?yot xes a em thguob uoy
emoC“ .lakcaj eht gnidir
”.thginot rof emag m’I tub
.pu gnilruc elzzum sih fo egde eht ,xof eht dias
.daerb derettub eht otni tib dna dehgis oeL ”.ysub er’uoy dna
,stsaot tI“ .retnuoc eht fo dne raf eht no tas taht ecnailppa nehctik egral eht ot gnitniop ,xof eht dias
,tsacdop siht no deraeppa taht yrots suoiverp a ot leuqes a
.ti ni sreniatnoc tuoekat ruof htiw gab citsalp a gnidloh ereht gnidnats saw ,oeL ,etammoor siH
,drawkwa fo dnik saw noitisop eht ecnis egarevel fo tol a evah t’ndid eH
”.won tuo taht ekat nac uoY“ .denihw lakcaj ehT
.hctiwt lakcaj eht edam ti yaw eht gnileef
.gniwollof erofeb dnoces a tsuj rof detatiseh dna
spil sih dekcil xof ehT
.derevihs xof ehT
elbat eht gnikcil ffo teg uoY“ .xelA deilper
.gnihtemos ro etabrutsam oG“ .yawa mih gnihsup ,oeL dias ”,on ,eduD“
.meht egnahc ll’I“
”.sgel ruoy tfil ot deen ot gniog er’uoY“
”tiF ti gnikaM“ saw sihT
”.ton od uoy“ ,xof eht dias ”,oN“
wap sih otno ebul erom emos detriuqs eH
,won eludehcs ym otni uoy tif syawla nac I ,hO“
.tfahs s’lakcaj eht no ecnuob elttil a gnivig
”?stonk cilrag eht revo drah tog uoY ?neht stonk cilrag roF“
.elzzum sih ta delkcit
”.taht ylpmi ot gniyrt ton m’I“
”?emoh ta azzip gnikooc trats I fi uoy deen t’now I deirrow llits uoy ,oS“
pu tas eh erofeb
”!yot xes a em thguob uoY“
”,uoy fo edisni ylecin stif yot ruoY .og ew erehT“
,kcab sih dniheb sdnah sih tup dna
ffo meht dekcik dna stnap krow sih ffo dellup tsrif lakcaj ehT
.yaw doog a ni ton dna ,skcus gnitludA
”?gninialpmoc er’uoY“ ”.llew oot yaW“
.xob eht ta dekool xof ehT
?ti t’nseod ,neht egatnavdasid a ta em stup taht ,lleW“ .gniggaw liat
doof s’xelA otni stigid owt gnikcits
.enihw ydeen a evag oeL
,lakcaj eht deksa
.yawa wap sih dellup dna dennirg oeL ”.ees I“
.kcab dial srae s’lakcaj ehT
”.thginot xes gnivah ton era eW
.detnaw oeL tahw ton s’taht tub
.gnisir flesmih ni noisnet eht gnileef
,tuo dnif nac eW .wonk t’nod I“
.noitartsurf eht dna ,noitsuahxe eht
”.won thgir ffo uoy gnikcus ton ma I ,xof gnikcuf yzarc uoY“
,doof netae-flah sih ta dekool xelA
.yaw eht fo tuo ti peek ot edis eht ot liat sih gnidloh
.pu atsap sih gninepo detrats dna
.demriuqs xof ehT
,mih htaenrednu kcub lakcaj eht tlef eh ylnedduS
”…yawa deirrac elttil a tog I oS“
”.taht fo etsat eht ,seY“
,emit evah syawla t’nod I semitemos wonk I“ ”.seY“
”.dnuora og ot ereht tuo sdoow ynam os ylno era ereht tub
.hctiwt xof eht edam ti yaw eht gnileef
”?yeht era ,em rof tsuj t’nera esehT
.etammoor sih gnilddarts
,seye sih desolc dna daeh sih koohs xof ehT
.atsap rieht gnitae
.yad eht fo dne eht ta em llac uoy nehw ecin s’tI“
.parts rehtael eht didnu dna
,trams er’ew fi tub ,seod ti ,seY“
”.uoy gnikcuf ton ma I
.detnaw eh enohp fo epyt tahw no dnim sih pu ekam t’ndluoc ohw yug eno siht dah I
”.ffuts fo stros lla seod ti ,seirf ria ti
,no desserp xof ehT ”.gniyrt m’I“
”.won dab taht t’nsi gnikooc yM
”.gnivil a ekam ot reisae eb ot desoppus
”,em no etartnecnoC“
htuom sih denepo eH ”?sgniht rehtO“
.tey tsuj ffo gnitteg t’nera uoy
.elbat eht ot revo deklaw dna
.niorg sih ot ruf s’xelA eht hguorht decart wap ehT
”.efil ym ni gniticxe gnihtemos od ot deen I sseug I“
”.ereh deit llits era sdnah ym ,yeH“
”?thginot od ot gniog uoy erew esle tahw ekiL“
,niaga emac xelA erofeb regnol tib elttil a koot ylno tI
,nac wen a nepo dluoc eH .dehgis dna
”.knird a flesym gnikam dna keew eht ni retal rof gnihtemos no gnikroW“
”.tuo dnif ll’uoY !ebyaM“
”,etammoor wen a deen ot gniog m’I“
”.uoy rof taht teg em teL“
.psag a htiw xelA dias ”,uoy kcuf ,hO“
,stonk tsom eht sekat reveohW
”.emas eht setsat ti
.mih ta dekool dna revo dellor lakcaj ehT
.nirg yls a xof eht evag lakcaj ehT ”.noitseuq eht si
.seye sih dellor eH
”.eromyna yreviled hcum sa gniod eb t’now ew sseug I“
pu tog lakcaj ehT
.wonk uoy ,yadot dekcus kroW“
.lakcaj eht fo tuo yot eht dellup yltneg dna seenk sih no pu kcab tog xelA ”!spoO“
.emit dnoces a tneps ton tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”?emit siht ti gnikat saw I dias ohW“
.pu eno dekcip lakcaj ehT
saw tI .pu dedne I erehw eb dluow siht kniht t’ndid I ,egelloc detaudarg I nehw oga sraey evif tub ,seY“
.mih otni tsurht ot deunitnoc lakcaj eht sa
”.taht rof ydaer m’I kniht t’nod …I“
.yzarc xof eht evord taht dna
.seigolohtna rehto dna gnaF
”!niaga muc ot gniog m’I kniht I ,wow hO“
.decamirg neht dna
sffuc eht fo eno detcennocsid eH ”.ma I tub
.eludehcs ruo ni tuoekat emos evah llits ll’ew erus m’I“ ”…lufrednoW“
”.yllaer drah eb t’ndluow ti ,ni meht evohs tsuj I fi erus m’I
ta rettiwT no dnuof eb nac eH
,yot eht denoitisop ylluferac eh dna
.ediw tnew seye sih dna ti detfil eH
meht fo htob dezeeuqs dna dennirg lakcaj ehT ”?siht ekiL“
,ycnegru gnisaercni htiW
”.uoy ot taht ekil ffuts od t’nod I ,yeH“
xob eht fo tuo meht dellup xof ehT
,deb eht no kcab dial dna og tel oeL ”.esaet uoY“
.gnihcnum tsuj fo etunim a retfa ,oeL deksa
.knird a teg ot egdirf eht ot revo tnew lakcaj eht sa ,xof eht dias
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
”?dnim ruoy no stonk cilrag dah uoy nehw detnaw uoy tahw siht saW“
”.hsaw ot sehsid eb lliw erehT .yako s’tahT“
.yawa dekool lakcaj ehT
.evol ew sgniht eht ni tif llits nac ew
?drah t’nsi boj ym kniht uoY“ .delworg xof ehT
,xof eht morf piy a htiw dna sgel sih detfil oeL ,yltneidebO
sffuc eht no gut saw od dluoc eh lla tub
.elzzum s’oeL no tog neve zzij sih fo emos ,drah os emac xelA
”.nwo ym no droffa dluoc I ecalp llams revetahw ot detaluger eb yllacisab d’I
.yot eht fo tsurht hcae htiw lakcaj eht tsniaga tonk eht sserp ot detrats eh sa noitnetta ot mih gninruter ydaerla
.enodnu erew trihs krow sih no snottub erom sa rae s’lakcaj eht fo egde eht desaet hteet prahs llamS
”.evitressa eb ot em dlot uoy dna ,yppah nosrep eno ekam nac I tub
.retal atsap eht taeher syawla dluoc eH
.derewol srae s’xof ehT
.hcamots sih no decnuob ti sa
”.uoy rof t’nsi eno sihT“
”.taht ekil dnuora em knay t’nod ,yako ,yakO“
,knird a flesmih xif yllanif ot eciuj elppaenip fo nac eht pu kcip ot tnew xelA sA
.retnuoc eht morf revo doof eht thguorb oeL
.tsehc reppu s’xof eht ssorca eugnot sih deggard eh erofeb
”?nehctik ruo ot gniod uoy era kcuf eht tahw dnA“
eeffoc rof tnahcnep a evah ot deromur si ohw rekamelbuort nwonk a si seyEthgiN
”,ekat t’nac I tonk eno s’tahT
”.ruf ruoy ni ecuas araniram tog ev’uoy ,oslA
,tsehc s’lakcaj eht derettalps muc xof
.tfahs gnibborht s’xof eht morf detriuqs muc fo tib rehtona dna
”.etsaw ot og ti tel ot tnaw t’ndid I dna ,eciuj elppaenip emos dellips I ,kooL“
,niaga gnimmuc ot esolc os m’I“
.trohs deppots dna
.tuo ti gnillup erofeb ni tigid a gnikcits
.moc.gnirpsyad-seyethgin
,enif gniod htob er’ew wonk I
.eciffo na dna moordeb s’dik loohcs hgih a neewteb ssorc a ekil dekool moor s’oeL
.odlid eht htiw repeed dehsup eh dna
.daerb fo seceip eht fo eno pu gnikcip dias eh
.sgnaf sih dekcil xof ehT
.llah eht nwod daeh ot denrut eh sa deggaw liat s’lakcaj ehT
.stonk cilrag fo yart tsrif eht nepo deppop oeL
”.dekan elihw elbat nehctik eht gnikcil er’uoy yhw wonk ot tnaw I oD“
”.yppah gnieb tuoba evitressa eB“
”.ti ekil t’nod uoy em lleT“
”.thginot su rof stonk htiw serutnevda oN .enif ,eniF“
rettub dna eseehc eht fo llems ehT
.spih sih delggiw xelA
.xelA dias ”,og uoy erehT“
.krow retfa tuo og ot yenom eht evah t’ndluow I
”.eludehcs ym otni uoy tif dluoc I dalg m’I tub
”!noitasrevnoc suoires a gnivah tsuj erew eW“
,uoy tcartsid I erofeb xis tae nac uoy fi dna
.tsehc s’lakcaj eht no dnah a decalp eH ”…tub ,seY“
eno siht piks nac uoy
.lakcaj eht fo pot no noitisop sih gniyojne detnap xof ehT
?tcerid oot taht sI“
revo xof eht dellup dna dennirg lakcaj ehT
”.nac I fi ees ll’ew dna ,worromot azzip emos em ekaM“
”,taht xif nac I“ .dennirg xof ehT
.ffulf tsehc s’xof eht ta dekcil eH
riahc sih ni kcab denael lakcaj ehT
”,emoh ta kooc ot reihtlaeh s’tI“
.naelc won elbat eht
”.etunim a ni erom gniwohs eb ll’uoy erus m’I
deggurhs lakcaj ehT
”.xes rof uoy esu tsuj I ekil dnuos ti ekam uoY“
”,em ot ti evig ,no
,nwod tas eh sa dennirg xof ehT
”.thgit m’I ,sulP .syawla toN“
.xelA ot dednah eh hcihw ,dnatsthgin sih morf xob draobdrac ralugnatcer a tuo gnihsif ,dias eh
.nirg a htiw oeL dias
”.su fo htob eht ecitne t’nseod gnivohs fo tib a fo tcepsorp eht taht yas ot toN“
.tuo yawflah ti gnillup erofeb
”.hguoht taht ekil uoY“
”.thginot ti tuohtiw enif eb ll’I tub ,dehsaw eb ot deen lliw retrofmoc ehT
,pu siht tpek eh fI
,pu tis ot deirt xof eht dna ,deggaw liat siH
.detnurg lakcaj eht elihw
.xof eht gnikorts ,dias eh ”,god ym ,hO“
”?nwo ruoy no ekat uoy did hcum woH“
ni em tif uoy nac tub
,ylwols ni yot eht deppils eh ,ylluferaC
,dlrow gnikcuf eht xif t’nac I llew ,haeY“
?xis ebyam ,eviF“
”.enod ev’uoy gniht tsedriew eht t’nsi elbat eht gnikcil uoY“
”?yawyna stonk ynam siht redro ew did yhW“
”.sgniht rehto fO“
”.siht hsinif ot deen uoY
,kcen s’xof eht ta dekcil dna nwod denael eh erofeb ,dias lakcaj eht ”,…thgiR“
,nehctik eht ni ereh muc ylisae dluow xof eht
.gel sih htiw elbat eht depmub eh sa
.detniuqs xelA ”?deffuts tonk teg ot tnaw uoy esuaceb ton s’tI“
,daed ni tseretni na dna
”,won em kcuf ot tnaw uoy woh gninnalp era yllaer uoY“
.flesmih desaeler eh sselnu
.kcen sih ta deppin eh yltneG
”?dlo gnitteg ew erA“
”?egdirf eht ni ffuts etihw fo pmul tnaig a ereht si yhW“
.tsehc s’oeL no flesmih gnipmuht ,dias xelA
.psarg s’etammoor sih ni demriuqs eh sa ,xelA dias ”,oN“
”,meht no gnikohc tuohtiw erusiel ruoy ta stonk xis lla ekat uoy fi ees s’teL .em yrT“
tsuj ot gnidiced
pu tnew srae s’oeL
”.mih morf elas a teg neve t’ndid I dna ,emit ym fo ruoh na pu dekcus eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.llib reh daersim ehs esuaceb thgiarts setunim ytnewt rof em ta demaercs ohw namow a dah I .sneppah tI“
”,ydaerla emoh er’uoy ,hO“
deb eht tsniaga kcab despalloc yeht detnetnoC
.htaehs sih fo tuo gnikcits pit knip eht was dna nwod decnalg eH ?drah eh saW
”?drah uoy era yhw dnA“
lakcaj eht otni knis yot eht gnileef
kcab sih otno flesmih deppolp dna
.resserd eht no xob eht tup dna
”.taht naht animats erom dah uoy thguoht I ,eniF“
.rennid htiw emoh tog oeL erofeb elbat eht naelc ot dedeen eh tub
.xelA deffuh ”,siht od nac uoY“
.niaga xof eht gnikorts detrats lakcaj eht yltneidebO
.daeh sih koohs lakcaj ehT
”,sseug I deticxe tog I“
”!uoy roF“ .oeL dias
”.tcennocsid em spleh tI
tenibac eht fo tuo setalp gnihsif ,oeL dias
.xof eht detsetorp
”.uoy ot tnatropmi era taht ni sgniht gnittif ta doog mees uoY“
.deb sih no nwod tas eh erofeb
,lakcaj eht morf tnurg a dna
”.swalc esoht htiw gniod era uoy tahw ees ot deen yllaer uoY“
”,trats ot htiw krow ot gniht eritne eht gnivah fo daetsni uoy no sworg ti nehw tnereffid s’tI“
”?edir a rof pu er’uoy knihT
”?ew t’nod ,nwod lla siht etirw ot deen ot gniog er’eW“
.stnap krow sih tsniaga deniarts noitcere nwo siH
.yadretsey tog I seirecorg eht fo flah ruoy yap t’ndid uoY“
.depoord srae s’xelA
”.azziP rof gnixoF“
,krims a htiw xelA dekramer
.tfahs s’xof eht ot sregnif sih denruter oeL
.htaehs sih dnuora sregnif parw ot nwod gnihcaer
,noisicerp elbmin htiw trihs sih no snottub eht fo tsom enodnu ydaerla dah xelA
.lebal repap eht gnippir
.tsehc s’oeL fo edis rehtie no swap sih decalp dna
,oeL ta dennirg dna revo deklaw xelA ”?tahW“
,hcamots s’xelA ssorca dils wap A
.nwod gnittis ,oeL dias ”,parC“ ”.yadretsey
,liat s’lakcaj ehT ”.od htob eW“
,gninekaew saw lakcaj eht htiw eit eht llet dluoc eh ydaerlA
”?sffucdnah rehtael deddap em thguob uoY“
.stonk cilrag fo syart owt tuo dellup dna gab tuoekat eht otni gud lakcaj ehT
.pih s’xof eht gnola dnah a nur ot tuo dehcaer dna dennirg lakcaj ehT
”,erofeb egasuas fo gnimaerd morf uoy deppots t’nsah tahT“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,pu dehsup dna krab desuma na evag lakcaj ehT
.elzzum sih dnuora wap a depparw oeL sa ,dias xelA ”!hpmm …si erehW“
erusaelp ni derepmihw xof ehT
.truh dluow ti tub ,ffo flesmih llup dluoc eh ,deirt eh fi dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.wap eht otni gnitsurht
.s’lakcaj eht tsniaga tfahs sih gnibbur ,xof eht deksa
”?uoy t’nod ,rennid pu gnikcip ekil uoY“
.ebul eht rof hcaer ot og tel eh erofeb
.pih sih hsurb dluoc noitcere sih os lakcaj eht ot esolc teg ot erus gnikam
.eciuj fo elddup eht ta gnippal detrats dna nwod denael eh
,ylwols yot eht detsiwt xof eht ylgnisaeT
”…gnikat eb dluohs ew pets a saw taht kniht t’ndid I tub
”,ffo em hsinif uoy litnu toN“
mih rof hcum oot saw yot eht yb noitartenep neddus ehT .oeL demialcxe
.lakcaj eht htiw eit eht gnitset
”.kooc ot woh wonk t’nod llits I tub ,yllaer toN“
ot drawrof denael xelA
”.namow emas eht s’ti
,selcsum fo gnir s’lakcaj eht pu debul yltneg xof eht tub
”.ecno ta elzzum ym otni lla ti evohs ton
.nwod elbat eht depiw eh sa ,xelA dias
.deggurhs xof ehT
saw gnikorts s’oeL
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.retnuoc eht no tsud ruolf eht ot gnitniop ,dias eh
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.ecafrus nedoow eht tsniaga llits eugnot
.deggurhs eH ”?neht ti si tahW“
”,flesmeht gniyojne si enoemoS“
”?elbat eht fo etsat eht sevorpmi tI
.tfahs tneps s’lakcaj eht pu regnif a decart xof ehT
.ti barg ot deirt eh sa ,xof der eht demialcxe ”!kcuF“
emoC“  .erusopmoc emos teg xof eht tel dna
.elpmis si egnellahc ehT“
.seenk eht ta tneb erew sgel s’oeL erehw
”.siht naht xaler uoy pleh ot noitcartsid retteb a evah ot gniog ton er’uoY“
tsirw sih ot parts eht fo dne rehto eht dekcilc xelA ”.seY“
,ecap nwo sih ta detnaw eh tahw koot oeL
.ssik tfos a oeL evig
”,tog uoy nevo retsaot ycnaf taht ni ti kooc nac ew os hguod azzip ekam ot gniyrt m’I
”.nrop ruoy nees ev’I sulp ,edis ruoy ot sdnah ruoy dloh I nehw deticxe os teg uoY
.dennirg lakcaj ehT
.roolf eht ta nwod dekool eH
.ttub s’xof eht tsniaga tfahs sih fo pit eht debbur eh sa ,deksa eh ”?ydaeR“
;emac yeht rehtegoT
,meht raew dluohs uoy ,emit txeN“
.yawa dnah sih dellup lakcaj ehT
.tsirw rehto sih no ffuc dnoces eht denethgit eh sa derevihs xelA
.riahc s’xelA tsniaga denael eH
regnif denekcils a kcuns lakcaj eht sa ,demialcxe eh ”!ho dna ,yakO“
,dekrej lakcaj eht dna
pu lla ti gnitteg hguorht yawflah saw eH
,detfihs eh ylwolS
”.emoh ton m’I nehw od uoy tahw S’TAHT os …hO“
.pu dekriuq elzzum s’oeL ”?oN“
,tuo dna ni flesmih gnihsup tpek elam rehto eht sa
gnilbbin eht morf ffo ekorb eH
”.erots eht ta tihs htiw gnilaed morf derit ton m’I naem t’nseod derob era dna emoh morf krow ot teg uoy esuaceb tsuj
.pit eht revo flesmih dekrow xof eht sa ,oeL deksa ”?pleh
.yot eht otno ebul detriuqs dna delims xof ehT
.ediw tnew seye s’xof ehT
.stonk eht fo eno pu dekcip dna
.rood eht desolc lakcaj ehT
.ecafrus eht ssorca regnif deddap a nar eH
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb ”tiF ti gnikaM“
.elbat eht rednu pmuht a saw ereht sa esirprus ni depley eH ”!yeh—
.htgnel s’xof eht pu delkcit stigid derruF
.flesmih tsujda ot nwod dehcaer xelA
drah llits rebmem gnihca s’xof eht
.ffo deppop ylisae taht dil a dah ti tub
”.won thgir esu nac ew gnihtemos s’tI“
,nac eht ssorca deparcs swalc siH
,sdnoces wef a rof ssa sih fo tfelc eht tsniaga pu bur tfahs eht tel xof ehT ”?retteB“
.siht htiw krow nac I tub ,hcum oot eb dluow etalp gnikcol A“ "—
.xof eht ta gnirats tsuj saw eH
.nalp a tog ev’I tub ,od I“
”.tsrif ebul erom deen uoY“
.rebmem gninedrah s’xof eht ta dezeeuqs wap A ”.I nac oS“
.derit m’I ,uoy dlot I“
.noitsuahxe ni deggas sredluohs sih tub
”.meht od ot ygrene eht evah llits ew elihw yllufepoh
.enips sih pu revihs a dnes taht tlef eh tub ,drah yletelpmoc t’nsaw xelA .dezeeuqs eh dna
,yllufyalp deggaw liat s’xelA
.etiuq ton tub ,esolC“
”.tonk eht htiw kcuts gnitteg peek I“ .dehgis lakcaj ehT
.ykcits llits s’ti tuB“
”.ebul eht dna ,yot eht em eviG“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,elbat eht morf pu dekool eh dna
,xof eht morf piy a dna troffe taerg htiw dna dennirg lakcaj ehT
.pmur s’xof eht otni
.stnetnoc sti gnillips ,elbat eht ssorca gnidils tnew dna ,wap sih fo tuo deppils ti
,won etammoor a dab taht ton m’I ,yeH“
”?evah uoy nalp siht si tahw dnA“
”.nehctik eht dnuora tfahs drah-imes ruoy gnihsalf si gniod er’uoy llA
”.etsat eht evorpmi ot desoppus s’tI“
.xof eht otni flesmih dnirg ot detrats oeL eht
gnihtyna yas t’ndid oeL
,detlih won xof eht htiW
.oot nrop ruoy nees ev’I“
.ffuh a htiw dias eh ”,eeS“
”?etsat eht evorpmi yllaer eciuj elppaenip seod ,oS“ .mih ot
etisbew sih no dnuof eb nac gnitirw sih tuoba noitamrofni dna
”.steehs ruoy fo ssem a edam ew ,hU“
eeffochtiwflow@
stigid sih denruter eh erofeb
dab a saw ti ,yrroS“
.hgual delffum a saw erehT
.mih htiw deit oeL ,yllaniF
”…mmM“ ”.ti tnaw uoy fi sruoy s’tI .gnisaet ton m’I“
.yad hguor a dah tsuj I
”…stonk dellac era yeht ,lleW“
.tnemom a rof detnap dna
.pu flesmih kcils ot xof eht rednu kcab
tonk gnillews sti dna kcoc drah s’xof eht ta gnikorts ,oeL dias
.doof netae-flah sih ta nwod dekool oeL ”.haeY“
drawrof deleviws srae s’xelA ”.mehA“
.deunitnoc oeL os ,deddon xelA
.xof eht ni deirub llits ,niaga gnimoc
.ereh em htiw kcits
.noitnetta sih thguac dnuos a nehw
”.semit owt tsal eht rof em ewo llits uoy tub ,ebyaM“
”.won redlo gnitteg lla er’eW“
gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
”.slaem nwo ym gniredro fo elbapac etiuq m’I
”?thgir ,stonk nezod a tog ev’eW“
,neht ecnelis ni tas yehT
.nwod em taeb efil tel t’nac I ,thgir er’uoY“
?no gnihtolc emos tup og uoy nac tub ,eniF“
.sevil ruo fo sraey tseb eht fo ynam yawa sekat dna emit gnikaw ruo fo tol a pu sekat tI
,nwo sih dna tfahs s’xof eht dnuora depparw wap A ”?ti siht sI“
.tnemirepxe gnikooc wen ym s’tahT !hO“
”,yltcerroc ti naelc em teL“ ”.ykcits
,sulP“ .deilper xelA
.mih ot txen deb eht no
”?gniylpmi uoy era tahw nehT“
”.tey taht rof ydaer ton m’I ,xelA“
,taeH ni deraeppa sah krow s’eyEthgiN
.mih htiw eit ot gniyrt
.tsrif eht fo tuo etib a koot dna ,deggurhs xelA
,sffuc eht tsniaga deniarts eh sA
”,uoy ot ti evig dluohs I fi wonk t’nod I tub ,nuf eb dluow siht gnikniht neeb ev’I“
.txen rennid tog ev’uoy esiwrehto ,stonk ruoy hsinif ,woN .egnellahc eht fo selur eht ksa t’ndid uoY“
”?tiaw ti t’ndluohS ?em roF“
,nwod tas eh erofeb yltcerroc tfahs s’oeL eht noitisop ot sdnah deffuc sih desu eh ecnayonna htiW
.dennirg lakcaj ehT
”.stonk cilrag deredro ew
,ti ta ylgnisaet delkcit eh dna
.tsirw sih no ffuc eht tif ot detrats xelA
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.selppin sih fo eno ta desaet hteeT
”.ylecin srevotfel yna pu taeh lliw nevo ycnaf tahT ?doog er’yehT“