”.rueisnoM ,dnal egnarts a ni regnarts a tub ma I“
”?nam yreviled dnik ,eman a evah uoy oD .raey siht
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
.anneiV fo secalap tsenif eht fo qcaJ gnidnimer
,redluohs s’qaJ no wap a decalp
ll’I“	 ”.57 hcnerF a yojne d’ohw epyt eht ekil kool uoY“
.esolc a ot emac cisum eht ,tsiteniralc eht morf hsiruolf etitep a htiw ,yllaniF
.tnemom feirb a rof dnuorg eht ffo drib eht gnitfil elihw deksa drapoel wons eht
.redluohs s’terref eht revo dekeep qcaJ
psirc a rof egnahcxe ni emid revlis ynihs a reihsac eht dils eh ,tnemgdelwonkca fo don yldneirf a htiW .dehcaorppa qcaJ
dnaB emiTdooG sih dna ralletS ynnhoJ tneserp ot duorp si ecalaP ecnaD muehprO ehT
.semirG hgielruB fo rewop eht htiw
xob ralugnatcer a laever ot ffo dil eht gniggut erofeb gnalc duol a htiw rab eht no ti tes eh sa qcaJ ta deralg eH
tekcop tsaerb sih otni dekcut erauqs nenil eulb psirc a ,esaerc tsethgils eht fo eerf saw tius yarg deroliat-ylbaccepmi siH
gniroolf teuqrap htiw detaroced ylhcir saw roiretni ehT
s’tI .osserpse fo puc a uoy ekam innavoiG evah nac I“
erehT	 .moor eht otni derehtils eh sa thgis fo enil s’aduoG dekcolb eH
.tuo niht ot nageb dworc eht litnu emit sih gnidib ,drawrof gnivom tpek qcaJ
.rolrap eht sdrawot wap reh devaw terref ehT ”?uelBeL erongiS ,eeffoc emos rof ni emoc ot ekil uoy
.mih evoba ria eht dellif nug ymmoT a morf stellub fo tat-a-tar eht sa skeehc s’qcaJ gnuts kcirb fo stiB .snac
eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
,kcab spets owt ,drawrof spets owt koot yeht sa smra rieht gnigniws riap eht ,mih decaf qcaJ
.eenk sih tsniaga kaetsfeeb nezorf a gnidloh rehto eht
erusopmoc sih niager ot htaerb peed a koot
”yrevileD A gnikaM“
qcaJ ”.ecnad taht no UOI na ekat ot evah ll’I“	 ”.esuoh eht no ecnad txen eht redisnoC“
.taoc hcnert sih fo tekcop tsegral eht edisni egakcap eht gnikcut ylluferac ,pu doots qcaJ
.sgnitsop lavan cificaP morf hserf sevom ecnad htiw stekcajeulb gnuoy tnarbiv ot
.aduoG gnilkcat erofeb selkcunk sih dekcarc tar kcalb ehT
ecnO	 .noitartsinimda s’gnidraH tnediserP ni noitpurroc tuoba yrots a ni kaeb sih gniyrub ,nepo ti deppilf eH .semiT eht fo noitide gnineve eht debbarg dna
dezingocer eh sreciffo ecilop lareves gnidulcni—mih dnuora dworc suocuar eht yb gnigduJ
”.uoy rof noitisoporp elttil a evah
.tixe erif a tuo dekcud qcaJ ,srehtaef liat sih fo kcilf a htiW ”.eihcrA ,retal uoy hctac ll’I .erom
.drawno meht gnigru cisum eht fo ygrene eht htiw teef rieht no thgil
.teertS retseH fo renroc eht no esuohnwot enotsnworb deniatniam-llew a dehcaer eh—
”?ylisae taht pils eht su evig dluoc uoy kniht yllaer ajdiD“	 .thgindim erofeb egakcap eht reviled ot emit fo ytnelp dah llits eh taht demrifnoc dna hctawtsirw sih dekcehc eH
.decamirg enimre ehT
.dleihs sih degdolsid tuoba gnippalf tekcaj sih fo ecrof eht
.sregnif sih deppans terref eht sa thgit pu gnihtyreve denottub ylluferac eH
.dworc eht fo ettelap roloc detum eht otni gnidnelb ruf nworb-tun
reweS cirtcelE ehT
.enotsnworb a fo yawrood eht otni dekcud qcaJ ,kcolb eht fo elddim eht dehcaer d’eh
.seotatop fo kcas a ekil deppord eh ,srehtaef s’qcaJ delruc taht lwoh a tuo gnitteL
.esac-ni-tsuj mra sih rednu ti dekcut dna
.seninac etihw ylraep sih gnihsalf ,dennirg drapoel wons ehT
drawkcab mih gnikconk
tahT“	 ”?emit dnoces a 57 hcnerF eht tseggus I thgiM“
pots reven dna ecnad ,ecnad s’tel oS
erew ysaekaeps ytpme-flah eht ni seye llA
”!flesruoy fo ecnasiun a ekam ot ’nitrats yllaer
,roolf ecnad eht dnuora yaj eulb eht delrihw eh sa qcaJ no dekcol erew seye eulb gnicreip s’drapoel wons ehT .regnarts a sserpmi ot gnicnad ekil gnidnuop doolb s’eno tog gnihtoN
.hguone suouconni demees ti ,wob elpmis a otni dettonk gnirts eulb fo eceip a htiw delaeS
”yrevileD A gnikaM“ saw sihT
,swap yffulf sih ni sregnif ylacs sih depsalc eh ,erauqs tekcop s’qcaJ dniheb flah rehto eht gnikcut retfA
”.sknird ruoy ot kcab oG
.eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
”!cainam uoy ,gniog er’uoy erehw
,otsug htiw devom eH
.tamrood eht ffo mih detfil dna taoc sih fo slepal eht yb mih debbarg erutalucsum dna thgieh lausunu fo terref A
.moob raw-tsop eht fo stcudorp wen rehto dnasuoht a dna
.seiticolev hgih ot stcejbo llams gnitarelecca ni trepxe na saw qcaJ
,ecnad eerf a rof nopuoc a saw tI
,innavoiG rof ksA .etag eht no noileksirt a
roolf ecnad eht evoba detniap—
.serocs degnahc artsehcro eht sa srepap fo gnilffuhs a saw ereht ,mih dniheB
,retnuoc eht dniheb tas xnyl lufhctaw A
yrrow ot gninnigeb saw I“
.srekoolno lla ot elbisiv aingisni DPYN
”.stnemilpmoc erecnis ym htiw nioc siht uoy gnoma rekcart tseb eht evig em teL
.sriats eht dednecsa qcaJ
.kooh thgir a rof pu gnidniw ,kcab tsif sih werd flow
.tuo egakcap eht gnillup
.drib taht tuo detniop taht eno eht m’I
elit eht no tuoba decnad latem eht sa roolf eht no tem ezag riehT .knilC
.taorht sih deraelc recnuonna
.mih no dekcol
.ereh noitisop a fo kceh a ni m’I .uelBeL ahctiw tsenoh eb annog
.wob lufecarg a drapoel wons eht evag
uoY“	 ”.noitseggus taht no pu uoy ekat ll’I“ .ssalg eht ot txen rallod revlis a dial dna
na ni uoy tup annog
.taoc ym edisni dekcut egakcap a evah
.eveels s’qcaJ pu repap fo eceip a dils drapoel wons eht
.slewot mraw ni depparw gnieb fo gnileef eht mih evag taht slarolf fo ydolem a ,tnasaelp saw tnecs siH .ffins lausac
.rueisnoM ,noitommoc eht rof seigolopA“
ylerem ma I .tnemhsilbatse gniknird enif siht fo snoitarepo eht tpursid ot ereh ton ma I“
.margorp egnahcxe ngierof a fo trap sa erofeb yad eht nileppez citnaltasnart aiv siraP morf revo emoc gnivah
gnilaed saw eh taht qcaJ ot delangis nip eit noileksirt dlog dna tius yarg taen A .ecnaraeppa derracs-elttab ,gninethgirf a mih gnivig
taht revo dnah
”.retsub ,dnoces a tsuj em eviG .ti tog
tsuj ll’I“ .gniw dehctertstuo na fo epahs eht ni tsac
kcab ti dekcut dna
”.ereh devirra I nehw innavoiG rof ksa ot dlot saw I
ydob ralugnatcer a htiw flow gnisopmi nA
,qcaJ ot txen deraeppa ylneddus dah ekoms ragic dirca fo duolc a ni depolevne terref A
”.ysae dna ecin ,revo ti kcik dna tag ruoy porD
,woN“	  .etercnoc dial-yliddohs eht ssorca deparcs pirg doow lrub eht sa ,thgit desolc kaeb ,decamirg eH
”.nosirapmoc yb suoiruxul kool yrrehs gnikooc sekam eniw rof esucxe elbisneherper
ll’I“	 ”.steg ti sa dab sa si eniw taht erus ytterp m’I .taht hctarcS“
recnuonna na sa sffur keehc suoiruxul s’drapoel wons eht hguorht sregnif sih ekorts ot egru eht detsiser qcaJ
.shgiht s’qcaJ fo ezis eht specib htiw
mih ta niets reeb cimarec ytfeh a dehctip qcaJ
.retaw htiw dellif esav latsyrc a htiw denruter innavoiG ”.esruoc
”.em sedecerp noitatuper
,madaM ,uoy htiw noitasrevnoc lufthgiled tsom a evah dluow I erus m’I ?og ot ti ekat I dluoC“ .dehgis
,evom txen sih gnitalpmetnoc ,ezorf yaj eulb eht sA
,detanoted dna tsehc eht ni erauqs regit eht tih ssalg ehT
.mahtoG fo erehpsomta eht gnirovas
.dworc eht otni eciov reh gnitaidar srekaeps dne-pot
.rouqil fo ward gnol a htiw kaeb
.niarb drib ,ysae taht yawa gnitteg ton ezuoY“
dnah ni eryl evitsef—
.sessalg latsyrc gnilkniwt ni snoitabil htiw hgih delip elbat a pota tniop egatnav a morf srecnad eht gninnacs eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo aduoG thguac qcaJ ”.esruoc fO“	 .noitca eht fo retnec eht ni noitisop emirp a derutpac yeht sa nirg a derahs riap eht
gnitteg ton er’uoy dna ,bub ,nug ymmoT wen a deen I“
wap a desiar regit eht ,seye sih ni srats htiw tuoba gnirettoT
”,ecnad eht yojnE“	  .tekcit repap
elzzum sih no sehctap sselruf lareves htiw ,llat sretem owt revo llew saw flow ehT
.elyts yratilim eht ni demmirt kaeb sih evoba egamulp krad eht
?esaelp ,em dnahnu uoy dluoC“
eh sa swalc yldaed s’regit eht degdod qcaJ ,ssentfiws naiva htiw gnivoM
I“	 ”.mih ssim ot tnaw t’ndluow I dna ,owt ta sesolc llah ecnad ehT
neht dna edisni seilil eht deppils terref ehT
.dezinorhcnys yltcefrep stnemevom rieht
eraps ot emit hcum evah t’ndid eH .mih no ni gnisolc saw tar eht taht mih dlot sesnes evitceted sih tub ,aduoG ees t’ndluoc qcaJ
ruoy kculp annaw t’nod eW
mih dniheb teerts eht drawot secnalg evitruf koot qcaJ
seuqcaJ ruetcepsnI
ehT	  .dworc gnineve eht fo tsdim eht ni gnidih yb moor gnihtaerb emos flesmih yub dluoc eh gnirugif ,edisni dekcud qcaJ .llarht a emid a rof lla
ehT	 .eciton s’aduoG eht edave ot deirt eh sa
.elbmesne sih ot roloc fo pop a gnidda
,pu esir ot emit dah eh erofeB
.thginot rof tnemeticxe hguone
”.namhcnerF a htiw ecnad
sihT“	 ”.em ees t’nod uoy fi ,eihcrA rof relles tekcit eht ksA“ .tahc-tihc rof
qcaJ	 ”.ereht tuo kcirb a
.yaw rieht ti gnidnes dna etercnoc eht no revlover sih gnittes ylregnig ,deilpmoc qcaJ
rof yrgnuh em tfel ev’uoY
”.gnihctaw eb ll’eW .dooG“	  ”.hguorht
uoy ekam ll’I“	 ”!srehtaef
,ronoh fo edoc niatrec a evah I .sriaffa lanosrep ym ni
ydolem tnasaelp a demihc yawllah eht ni kcolc rehtafdnarg ehT
aob rehtaef dna sserd dedduts-enotsenihr a ni tevic eht fo ecnalg feirb a ylno thguac qcaJ ,mhtyhr emas eht ot gnivom seiceps dna redneg yreve fo sriap rehto fo sderdnuh yb dednuorruS
”.dlog taht gnikat eb ll’I“
.ysaekaeps eht rof tnorf a sa devres taht
.ytiniffAruF no krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,mih tuoba rewop denifer fo ria na dah eH
regit a yb denioj saw flow ehT
gninniw-drawA oeL eht gnidulcni
,tfird ym hctac uoy fi ,lanosrep rehtar era stnetnoc ehT
dnaH“	  .dediser yllausu ti erehw
.gnirts eht odnu ot
.qcaJ ta revlover dettip-tsur a delevel
qcaJ	 .tnetnoc s’traeh sih ot ti od dluoc eh ,srallod ytnewt htiw dna ,eihcrA htiw yawa serac sih ecnad saw od ot detnaw eh llA
.diuqil knip noen htiw dellif ssalg gniripsrep a mih thguorb rednetrab eht sa daeh sih dekcoc qcaJ
redle fo htgnel devrac-dnah a ,tnemurtsni gnikool-elbadimrof a saw tI
.seenk sih tneb dna kcab sih denethgiarts qcaJ sa daeh s’regit eht ni denrut
,esaelP“	 ”.emid a ylno s’tI ?ecnad a rof erac uoy dluoW‘
,retnuoc eht otno pu pael ot detpmetta regit eht sA ”!gnul nori
”.neht htlaeh s’resiaK eht ot tsaot
.ekahs kciuq a ti gnivig dna
,edisa ti gnihsuP
eiddE sa sretsop detnaw eht morf mih dezingocer qcaJ
.erawrab lluf-flah htiw erif denruter
”?ay era ,ereh dnuora morf ton
sdnah sih ni revo ti gninrut ,noitcepsni yreviled-erp feirb dradnats sih ti evag qcaJ
.flah ni ti erot yltaen dna swalc s’qcaJ morf tekcit eht dekculp ylluferac eH
,poots eht no doots eh sa eeffoc gnimaets eht fo pis a koot eH
gnirud dereffus d’eh yrujni na yb detatissecen
.regnif yknip sih denroda taht gnir tengis dlog eht htiw delddif ylsuovren terref ehT
,flesmih ydaets ot retnuoc eht otni swalc sih gud
er’uoY“	 .dlrow siht rof gnol ton saw noitibihorP—
.tnemngissa siht fo erit ot gninnigeb saw eH .dehgis qcaJ ”?ruoh siht ta ereh siht dnuor gnimoc ’niod er’uoy kniht ayddahW“
.notab sih desiar rotcudnoc eht sa elims suoegrog a dehsalf xof ehT ”.ruoH rewoP lyhtE ocaxeT eht rof
delggurts terref eht ,msitamuehr htiw delrang sregnif htiW ”.emit ni
qcaJ sA .lootsrab eht pota hcrep sih morf mih egdolsid ot qcaJ devohs yleuqsurb flow ehT
liated etisiuqxe hcus ni deredner daeh s’nogroG a
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,eizarG“	 ”.rewop nwo ym rednu enrobria gnieb referp I
.drib elttil ,hguod eht revo
erofeb mia sih no qcaJ tnemilpmoc ot fi sa
,lriws feirb a ti evag eh sa elahni peed a koot dna ni denael qcaJ .mih fo tnorf ni ssalg deppihc a detisoped enimre ehT
.tfihs dnoces eht morf emoh gninruter snezined draggah eht htiw ni dnelb ot nwod daeh sih gnipeeK
I“	 ”.drib ,’nikauqs trats retteB“
I“	 ”?dnim ni evah uoy od tahW“
ehT	 .egats eht otno pu debmilc—
,ffo flesmih detsud eH
,yawa ecnatsid emos tar eht fo espmilg a thguac eh sa seye sih deworran qcaJ
ni ti gnihsiugnitxe
dils eh sa deddon qcaJ
.goms lacimehc ,kciht a htiw ria eht gnillif
ot ecnalbmeser gnikirts a erob noitcocnoc eht dezilaer qcaJ ,pis suoituac a gnikaT
redluohs s’qcaJ dehsurb yllufyalp odexut desserp-ylpsirc a ni drapoel wons A
”.uoy nraw t’ndid I yas t’noD“	 ”!ueiD noM“
.repap gnipparw revlis tlig ni derevoc
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
erofeb ralloc sih gnitsujda
.gnitadimitni naht suolucidir erom dekool eh thguoht qcaJ
.tsap dellorts eh sa mih revo thgir gnidils ezag s’aduoG ,repapswen eht fo pot revo ybsressap eht dennacs eH
.maet trepxe na yb nwod nekat neeb ev’I smees tI .snoitalutargnoc
.swalc sih dednetxe regit ehT ”.t’nod ew
.krims gnisaet a htiw dias drapoel wons eht ”,pu peek ot
.enac sih dnuora parw ot nwod detrad dnah s’qcaJ sa
.koob erocs eht hguorht yldipar gnippilf ,ygrene citenerf htiw notab sih gnuws—
.stcejbo ynihs ynam os deniatbo gnivah fo thguoht eht ta skeehc sih hguorht gnitaidar erusaelp lasab
,gnir dehctip-hgih a htiw tser ot emac tI ”.spoO“
.snettim suoiruxul fo riap a ekil meht gnipolevne
”?flesruoy
”!uoy fo lla naht rehguot m’I evorp ot sdrow ’niknits on deen t’nod
.dleihsdniw snas won racrotom rieht
,spets owt retfA
t’nsI“	 ”.em rof egakcap a reviled ot uoy deen I .yllaer ,elpmis s’tI“ .shtnom lareves ni edam eh naht erom saw mus ylecnirp ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.srotaderp xepa eht yb defrawd gnieb etipsed hgih kaeb sih dleh qcaJ ”.tuo siht klat nac ew erus m’I .sffucitsif ot dnecsed ot deen on s’erehT“ ”.me‘ teg s’teL“ .htgnel lluf rieht gninnur yalni dlog dna revlis htiw ,sevink kaets sa egral erew yehT
yrtsepat hsimelF yrutnec htneetneves A
.elbbauqs ot trats meht dehctaw eh sa etteragic sih no ward peed a koot qcaJ .meht fo htob ta derutseg taes regnessap eht morf tuo deppets eh sa dekaerc sgnirps s’nades eht taht hguone ythgiew tar kcalb A ”.drib
”.taht tcepser nac I .retoohs thgiarts a er’uoY“	 ”.dnatsrednu uoy erus m’I gnihtemos
.evirra uoy ecno ,namrood eht
.sblub derolocitlum fo sdnasuoht htiw pu til gnidliub tauqs a drawot teerts eht ssorca detnirps qcaJ ,revoc rof tpael star eht sA
s’tahT“	 .noitnetta sih thguac ”meh-
.spihc onisac eulav-wol erew yeht fi sa
.ehcuob-esuma na tub saw ecnad
.duht tew a htiw daeherof eht ni retnec daed mih dekcams tI
htiw enotsnworb a ees ll’uoY“ .terref eht dias
,gof latsaoc a ekil slirtson sih morf dewolleb
”.evah uoy der tseb eht em eviG .eniw emos evah
revlover sih debbarg qcaJ ,yawa dellorts eh sa ”esialliesraM aL“ gniltsihw yllausaC
.seikooc derovalf-ecirocil
erotskoob ybbahs eht otni tuo dedaeh dna ralloc sih pu denrut yaj eulb eht ,knird sih gnihsinif retfA .dworc eht otni dedaf ydaerla dah terref eht tub ,redluohs sih revo daeh sih denrut qcaJ
.loots eht ffo deppoh eh sa ,dias qcaJ
yrT“	 .staeb gnuws eht ot denutta yltcefrep
thgin eht hguorht lla sliat esoht ekahS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.aibohportsualc s’qcaJ etaba ot gnihton gniod sretsop htiw denil sllaw dna gniliec wol eht
m’I“	 ”.dluow uoy fi ,noitcepsni ym rof egakcap eht tuo gnirB“
.sgnidnuorrus sih ot kcab noitnetta sih gninrut erofeb efas erehwemos ti dekcut dna delkcuhc qcaJ
.thginot enoemos teem dluow I desimorp I tub
”.rovaf a em gniod eb yllaer d’uoY
.kcol etarobale sti no devargne noileksirt nedlog a erob etag nori tsac A
ezuoY“	 ”.dnuorg hgih eht evah I !ima nom ,inif tse’C“
.tamrood eht otno qcaJ deppord yleuqsurb innavoiG
ta ylsuoiruc dereep sessalgeye dellif-dlog htiw terref ylredle nA
.roolf eht dnuora qcaJ gnidiug swap decneirepxe sih ,ecnad eht del drapoel wons ehT
yeH“	 .srengised eunevA htfiF morf snoihsaf retniw tsenif eht ni seidal dna eit kcalb ni nemeltneg htiw senin eht ot desserd lla ,srecnad ixat eht
.knird denodnaba na no delttes
ammaM alled atseF aL nettogrof d’eh taht
”!haG“	  .ecalaP ecnaD muehprO eht drawot kcab ffo tes eh ,pets sih ni gnirps a htiw ,nehT
bruc eht deppoh nades yruxul kcalb a sa sdrawkcab flesmih werht qcaJ .noitnetta sih thguac enigne thgie-thgiarts a fo raor gniyfisnetni eht ,seman teerts tnirp-llams eht enimaxe ot kaeb sih ot pu ti dleh eh sA .pam tsiruot a dedlofnu eh sa sgniraeb sih teg ot klawedis eht no desuap qcaJ
.retsiniM emirP saw uaecnemelC segroeG nehw dehsaw tsal saw ti ekil dekool taht gar rab a htiw ssalg initram a nwod depiw ehS
,wap eno ni ehcolc revlis a htiw deraeppa flow ehT
.rettab epêrc neklis ekil eugnot sih ffo gniwolf sdrow eht
nwod gninrub si sucric eht dnA snwolc lla er’ew sdneirf ym ,ecnad ,ecnaD
.tfil mumixam rof drawnwod smra derehtaef sih gnipeews
…daer ot ikahK rof ysae s’ti os stnedni on htiw lairA stp61 si siht dna ,thgin ymrots dna krad a saw tI  DNE .gnineve na dneps ot yaw dab-flah a t’nsaw yreviled a gnikam desoppus
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf
.rac gnildi eht fo dleihsdniw eht otni rednilyc s’revlover eht gniytpme
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
.tsehc sih pu deffup eh sa nwod wap s’aduoG deppals esuom ehT ”.uoy ton ,mih dnuof I ?’niod er’uoy kniht ayddahW“
”.wonk uoy ,ecno llij gnuoy a saw I .dnatsrednu
.kni der ni renroc eht ni delbbircs traeh llams a htiw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
srehtaef sih delffur qcaJ
hctaW“	 .oga dnoces a tsuj gnidnats neeb d’eh erehw deppots dna
repap eht dedlof yltaen eh ,yawa ecnatsid elbatrofmoc a saw tar eht derugif qcaJ sa noos sA
.tnerruc sseltneler ni taob a ekil drawrof mih tpews dworc eht dna degnahc thgil ehT
.nudreV fo sehcnert eht ni nioc cnarf-evif dlo na morf denoihsaf d’eh eceip ytfeh a ,gnir sih htiw delddif qcaJ .eiv ed uae fo gnivres a rof gniromalc serutaerc ynam eht fo rehtona evres ot yawa deirrucs rednetrab ehT
.star eht ecnartne ot retsul sti gniwolla ,egde sti yb nioc eht dleh eH
.yppans ti ekam dnA“ .tcelletni fo hpmuirt a eriuqer dluow noitautis sihT
.esolc a ot werd gnos eht sa
wal eht yebo ot evirts I tub ,yenom ysae nwod nrut ot eno ton ma I“ .retnuoc eht ffo nioc a dekculp eh sa walc xedni sih htiw elzzum s’ytrebiL ydaL enipluv eht deppat qcaJ ”.ecirp ym fo noitcarf a rof yreviled elpmis a eldnah dluoc yobswen yna erus m’I ?llikrevo tib a siht
,erif denruter qcaJ
”!ffo looc ot srekiR ni lla uoy worht t’nod I dna ,yawa og uoY .laed a
s’tI“	 ”.flesruoy sa rebilac hcus fo rentrap ecnad a evah I netfo ton s’tI“ .elbayojne erom eht lla ti edam ria eht ni regnad fo tnerrucrednu eht ,ecnad elgnis a rof emit evah ylno dluow eh erus ylriaf saw qcaJ elihW
.nwod htob meht derats eh sa kaeb sih otni eno kcuts dna—
eye sih sa eit depirtsnip sih denethgiarts ylluferac eh ,mih htaeneb dekaerc eenk sih sa enac eht no ylivaeh gninaeL
sa somrehT a morf eeffoc fo puc gnimaets rehtona flesmih deruop eH .ygrene htiw gnitarbiv ,retnec eht ta htoob a deipucco ralloc dnab dna
.evlewt kcurts ti sa
”.ahctiw klat ot stnaw reganam ehT ?won ysae dna ecin ,em htiw emoc uoy t’nod yhW .drib elttil ,em ot noegip-loots a ekil ’nikool ezuoY“
.aduoG ,enim si dlog tahT“
retsloh redluohs eht morf revlover 2981 elèdoM ytsurt sih barg ot detrad dnah sih sa denworf qcaJ
,leef laitalap a ti evag gniliec hgih s’roiretni ehT
.yltcefrep ni dednelb
.ni lla ti gnikat ,kcab denael uelBeL ercaiF
I“	 ”?thginot retal gnikrow eb uoy lliW“
.tnemele sih ni yllatot saw yaj eulb eht
”.nrecnoc rof deen on s’erehT“
.nageb srentrap hserf rof elbmarcs eht sa roolf ecnad eht revo emac noitommoc taerg A
,rab eht otno drawkcab depael eh
qcaJ	 .roolf eht otno drawkcab gnispalloc
”yrevileD A gnikaM“   yojne esaelP
”,tuo flesym ees
.ecrof suodnemert htiw eenk s’flow eht tsniaga ti gnihsal erofeb namwohs sucric a ekil enac sih delriwt qcaJ ,naiva na fo emit noitcaer roirepus eht gniyolpmE
.erihppas rimhsaK a fo roloc eht erew seye siH
.lagelli ’nihton t’nia tI“
”.doog s’ti esimorp t’nac I“	  .raW taerG eht
tahW“	 .taoc hcnert savnac sih edisni dekcut dleihs DPYN eht fo thgiew eht ot desu etiuq t’nsaw llits eH
sih tew ot tiaw t’ndluoc eH
eldnah dekooh a htiw doow
,emigér neicna eht fo ytilibon eht htiw flesmih deirrac qcaJ
erih rof elbaliava bac elgnis a tops ot deliaf gnivah—klaw ot derac eh naht skcolb erom
,nirg a gnirahS .draobyek eht ssorca decar sregnif s’reyalp onaip eht elihw
erohcispreT fo larum evissam eht
.tellug sih nwod delkcirt ylluficrem eniw eht ,xelfer gag sih htiw elggurts feirb a retfA
.egnahc ot thgil ciffart eht rof detiaw eh sa elop latem derettab a tsniaga denael yaj eulb
tsuJ“	  ”.esimorp a nekorb reven evah I dna
etirovaf sih fo kcap a deveirter eH
,roolf eht ot nwod ylizal detfird gnirts eht ,tuc tfed a htiW
.enohporcim eht ot pu deppets taht
sesioluaG—setteragic
.tnemhserfer fo deen ni
.ecnartne eht dna qcaJ neewteb flesmih decalp dah drapoel wons eht ,tnedicca yppah a yB
.nepo welf srood eht sa ffo flesmih detsud qcaJ
.repapllaw eulb peed dna
.ria thgin gnihserfer eht otni tuo dedaeh eh erofeb don etilop a reh evag qcaJ
”!ecils a tnaw ew dna ,frut ruo no egral wef a gniyrrac ezuoy wonk eW
,thgindim erofeb edam yreviled siht detnaw yletarepsed enoemoS“
yamsid yb detpmet oot leef t’noD
.mih dehcnerd sknird fo yteirav a sa noisolpxe yrotcaf eyd a ot rednatsyb a fo ecnaraeppa eht no koot regit ehT
yawa serac ruoy lla ecnad ,ecnaD
”!reziteppa dael a pu evres ot yppah m’I tub
.qcaJ ta gniralg elihw dias aduoG ”,egakcap
ro srentrap dehctiws snortap eht sa cisum eht ni esuap a saw
ot erusaelp eht evah I netfo ton
qcaJ	 .woleb srecnad eht no thgil cirtcele tsac sreilednahc latsyrc suomronE .dlog tarak ruof-ytnewt ni dedlig seniltuo htiw smrof cirtemoeg htiw detaroced erew sllaw ehT
.nwod deppoh eh sa
edaf ot demees egaruoc s’regit ehT
.dehcter eh sa timov ot ton elggurts ot mih gnicrof—os ylgnitsugsid—teews-ylkcis saw tI
namdooG ynneB fo noitaler tnatsid a—rotcudnoc ehT
.thgif ot deen on s’ereht ,nameltneg ,esaelP“
.ylriaf thguof ylerar slanimirc ,thgif thgiarts a ni stnedor eht ekat ot elba eb thgim eh detamitse eh elihW
erofeb etteragic sih no ffup tsal eno koot eH
.slaeppA fo truoC eht morf snoisiced tsetal eht fo swen htiw rovaf eht denruter ohw sreywal htiw spit kcots gnidart sreknab ,laivoj saw erehpsomta ehT
,tnecca hcnerF yvaeh a htiw ekops qcaJ
.stnetnoc sti ot sa ffo qcaJ pit ot ti no sgnikram on erew erehT
tops ot ysae saw tI
dluoW“	  .etulas yratilim psirc a reh evag qcaJ
ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.ereh acuL htiw elkcip a fo kceh a ni eb ll’uoy ro thgindim erofeb ereht ti teG
”.nwod drib eht tel nac uoY .innavoiG
etilekaB gnimaets a htiw denruter innavoiG sa dnah s’qcaJ otni
.xificurc yrovi na htiw dialni elbat ynagoham ralucric a no ronoh fo ecalp a ni meht tes
liated ylno eht eit dlog tnecsediri sih
ehT‘ ,enut wen rieht fo tubed eht yojne esaelP“
ym reffo ot ekil d’I ,tsrif tuB“
”.madaM ,srewolf eht yojnE .puocuaeb
.smra sih dessorc dna tnemevap eht no nioc eht dessot yllausac
.yawa klaw dna klawedis eht no tuo ti ssoT“
.evig ot ssel dah ydob sih ,gnilliw saw tirips sih elihW .hgiht
.ksam reh dnuora gniniamer nworb fo sehctap wef a ylno htiw ,munitalp denrut dah ruf ynwat reH .mih
dnatsswen a fo retnuoc eht otno lekcin a dessot yaj eulb eht
?yas uoy ,egakcap A“ .elims reh ni tnedive saw tiw prahs a
relevart elbmuh a
.edalbhctiws a nepo dekcilf innavoiG
.tekcaj sih otni swalc sih gniggid
.taes s’revird eht fo tuo deppets tius depirtsnip a ni tar nworb A
,hcnup a worht ot detovip regit eht sA
,stcaratac htiw deduolc erew seye reh hguohT
.ssentcerid s’drapoel wons eht detaicerppa qcaJ ”.rueisnoM
,aciremA ni lavirra hserf a saw eH
.ylgnicanem delworg flow eht sa seye sih dellor qcaJ
repsihw a ot nwod deppord yletaidemmi noitasrevnoc fo raor ehT
,nodnaba dliw htiw qcaJ ta dehsals eh hguohT
.revlis gnilrets morf detfarc remmahegdels a ekil
.esacriats ediw eht etisoppo llaw eht denroda
.spoO“	 .yot s’buc a ekil
a drapoel wons eht evag qcaJ ,detiaw yeht sA
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.thgil egnaro mraw htiw
renni sih pu toohs niap tlef qcaJ
.rolrap eht otni deraeppasid innavoiG ,ylsseldroW
.pu til seye s’qcaJ
.klawedis eht nwod delbboh eh sa srehtaef sih delffur ezeerb llihc ylgnihserfer A
.lwarb hsinootrac a otni dednecsed gnaG eseehC giB eht erofeb tnemom a rof degnahcxe erew slwocs elitsoH
sleehW	  ”.etaf emas eht reffus uoy erofeb evael em tel uoy tseggus I .lufniap dekool tahT“ .etteragic
seigolohtna suoremun ni dehsilbup neeb sah krow s’xuaF
,depmarc saw ybbol
.worb reh no yvaeh gnittis smeg etsap neerg htiw dedduts arait a ,sserd htgnel-elkna ,yknils a ni enimre rednels a saw rednetrab ehT
,pu dellor gnaG eseehC giB eht fo tser eht ,retal tnemom a toN
.eit sih denethgiarts flow eht sa selkcunk sih dekcarc regit ehT
.ffihw peed a koot terref eht ,elzzum reh ot esolc meht gnignirB .klis laicifitra htiw
”.owt ta ffo teg
til steerts eht tpek serianimul nori-tsac ,mid saw noom eht
dnuob seilil etihw sselwalf fo teuquob a dial edisnI
.artsehcro eht ffo dekcik enilssab gnipmuht a dna retsiger omissitla eht ni maercs ot nageb teniralc a erofeb esualppa fo dnuor feirb a saw erehT
,teuqorc fo semag evititepmoc ylsuoiciv gniyalp pu nworg gnivaH
yM“	 ”.laed a tuc ot gnilliw er’uoy fi syob ym ot did tsuj uoy tahw erongi ll’I
ehT	 ”.tsepmet eht paer llahs dniw eht swos ohw eH .ylluferac daerT“
.setteragic fo kcap sih dna nioc dlog elgnis a deveirter dna tekcaj sih otni dehcaer qcaJ ”.esruoc fO“	 ”.thgin lla tog t’nia eW
,rab eht tsniaga denael enac siH
.nepo welf rood eht
.yrtnuoc dlo eht ot kcab em ekat esehT“
.diulf rotaidar fo eliforp rovalf eht
.noilimÉ-tniaS tuohguorht sremotsuc ot seip s’rehtom sih gninnur doohdlihc sih fo sremmus gnol eht tneps dah eh ,ssenisub reiruoc eht fo tuo nettog dah qcaJ elihW ”.dnatsrednu I“	  ”?ehcipaC .thginot dereviled eb ot evah yeht dna
.repap fo eceip eht revo kcehc ot llul feirb eht desu eH
”!naem uoy tahw aedi tsethgils eht t’nevah I“	 .trihs sih deniats diuqil nworb llud eht sa
ekoms sa kaeb sih ni gniredloms etteragiC
,tekcaj sih fo tekcop renni eht otni dlog fo elip ythgiew eht
tekcaj htgnel-tsiaw dettif a ni hateehc A
fO“	 ”?eh t’ndid ,uoy tnes nos yM
,llat sretemitnec ytxis derdnuh-eno naht erom yldrah saw eh hguohT
seenk dna swoble eht no sehctap deilppa-ylitsah lareves htiw tius erabdaerht a ni esuom A
.seran lanretxe sih ot pu gnisir snisiar fo amora gnorts a
.xuaedroB tsenif eht gnitteg eb yltcaxe t’ndluow eh taht wenk qcaJ ”,noitibihorP“ dellac daf naciremA wen eht fo erawa-lleW
.retal tnemom a gniwollof repap gnipparw eht
m’I“	 ”!gnineve tnasaelp esiwrehto na gniniur eno eht er’uoy ,dnats I erehw morF“ .egnar fo tuo ylnrobbuts deniamer eh
tnemngissa na sees syawla uelBeL ruetcepsnI“
nit delemane llams a desserp terref ehT
.kcen sih fo kcab eht no srehtaef eht delsuot htaerb toh s’flow eht sa lartuen deniamer noisserpxe siH
.levon eitsirhC ahtagA derae-god a hguorht gnippilf
.decaf-der dna gnitnap ,pu deggoj aduoG sa delbmessa dna tuo debmilc yehT
”.gnitaralihxe etiuq saw tahT“
.plug elgnis a ni kcab eniw eht demmals qcaJ ,ecamirg a htiW
.stekcit ecnad lanoitidda esahcrup ot hateehc eht ot dedaeh
.gnaG eseehC giB eht fo daeh eht ,neslO ”aduoG ehT“
retfA	  .degnoleb ti erehw
.raB terreF kcalB eht ta moolb lluf ni erew seitnewT gniraoR ehT
,tekcubtsriht latot a ekil gnitca er’uoY
uoy erA“ .tuo ekam dluoc yaj eulb eht
.stunod elats dna eeffoc paehc ekil dellems htaerb siH
egabrag fo riap a dniheb nwod gnittauqs ,yawyella na otni dekcud ylkciuq qcaJ
,revoc rof snairtsedep wollef sih no yler regnol on dluoc eh ecnO
”’.gniwS sucriC
retnuoc eht no selgae elbuod rallod-ytnewt fo lufwap a deppord terref eht sa tseretni s’qcaJ thguac dlog fo gnip evitcnitsid ehT
.gniliec ekil-lardehtac eht koohs noitces ssarb eht sa ytisnetni gnizalb htiw gnola devom opmet ehT
”.ecivres ertov à ,uelBeL seuqcaJ .uelBeL“
.ria thgin looc eht fo htaerb peed a koot eh ,enac sih no dnah a gnitseR
.elbarrefsnart erew slliks eht erus saw eH
.enots ot nrut selcsum sih tlef qcaJ
.ybur ynit a ekil dewolg pit ehT
,eeffoc ,setteragic gnikwah ,enilyks eht pu til sngis noeN
hguohT	 .torioP elucreH fo stiolpxe eht naht edistuo snairtsedep eht no desucof erom raf demees eH
,ciffart htiw dekohc erew steerts eht ruoh siht ta nevE
heh“ prahs a ,ssalg eht dnuora depparw swalc sih sA
”.sserpxE ynoP eht ton ma I“	 ”.yreviled a rof etal yllufwa s’tI
.secnad citsur gnimrofrep srytas dna shpmyn fo slarum rellams yb dednuorrus saw tI
.regit eht ta ssalg tnip a erif ot
,teews htiw kaeb sih deffuts eh sa sregnif sih neewteb snioc dlog eht fo eno delddiwt qcaJ
.yltnatcepxe wap sih tuo dleh aduoG
”.serehwon gniog t’nia ezuoY“	 ”.rueisnoM
.ecnartne eht hguorht dekcud qcaJ sa kniw suoitatrilf a mih gnivig ,dias hateehc eht
weksa-flah seitkcen htiw nemssenisub ssalc-hgih morf gnignar ,efil fo sklaw lla morf emac snortap ehT
”?retae-ekac ,uoy teg I nac
qcaJ	 ”!taht fo yaw eht ni
”,retseH dna yrrebluM fo renroc eht ot siht ekat nehT“ ”.nob tse’C“ .dnuora delttar gnihton taht hguone thgit dekcap erew stnetnoc ehT
,oN“	 ”?ynniV ew od ,ereh dnuora sreppoc ot yldnik oot ekat t’nod eW“
,enohporcim nobbir eht fo emorhc eht otni deruop eciov yksuh s’regnis ehT
”?niarb drib ,emit tsrif eht em raeh ay t’ndiD“	 ”.tnemhserfer
gniyojnE“	 pot sucric gnimalf eht dnuorA
.thginot uoy rof taert laiceps a evah I ,nemeltneg dna seidaL“
,serneg ynam ssorca gnitirW
eit wob a ni xof emosdnah a—
.uoy rof guns dna ecin pu depparw ydaerla s’tI“
thgil gnizalb ni ecnad ,ecnad s’tel oS
.yarthsa nialecrop deppihc a
I“	 ”?thgir ,sdrow htiw etupsid elttil siht elttes lla nac uoy erus m’I
”.marcs dna pord eht ekam si od ot evah uoy llA
otsug htiw edils sih demmals tsinobmort ehT
,euqsetorg saw rekconk ehT ”…ueiD noM“
.artsoN asoC eht htiw
eldnah eht desu dna dnuora enac sih deppilf qcaJ ,level sih ot pu bmilc ot detrats regit eht sA
icreM“	  ”.hcamots ytpme na htiw emoh s’olleviC arongiS sevael eno oN .yenruoj ruoy rof ecnanetsus elttil a ekat ,esaelP“ .puc
sih fo pit eht ot hctam a gnignirb rehto eht ,enac sih no dnah eno detser qcaJ sa
”.drib elttil ,ereht
?uelBeL ,thginot hguod elttil a gnikam ni detseretni
.yeH“	 ”?taht wonk uoy
,em no azzip a evah ton yam I“
,kroY weN fo lla ni srecnad ixat tsenif eht derutaef ecalaP ecnaD muehprO eht taht decnuonna ylduorp eeuqram ehT
.rab eht rednu morf elttob a debbarg enimre eht sa retnuoc kcolb rehctub eht no swalc sih demmurd qcaJ