.niboR ta delims ehS
.llaf reh wols ot stipmra eht rednu reh hctac mih gnittel ,mih nioj ot nwod deppoh ehS
.elggig a revoc ot esor regnif reH
.teef sih ot mih llup reh tel dna wap reh koot niboR
.revo ti dekool ehS
.trat dellifrevo na ekil tsrub t'ndid ti rednow a saw ti ,seitilibisnopser htiw deffuts os doots eltsaC mahgnittoN
.dekrow nalp eht tnerappa emaceb ti ecno rellat sehcni wef a gniworg
.pu gnurps srae s'nairaM
".meht hsauqs ot elbail si kcas a ni meht gnittuP"
.retal tnatsni na dewollof reh fo tser ehT
,niht oot ti edam hcnarb eht ni edivid a litnu decnavda yeht
.dluoc I kniht t'nod I"
.del sliart emag erehw dna
.edirp htiw reh ot dekool niboR
".em ot emas eht kool lla seert ehT
,tpews eh shguob pu dna seert dnuorA
.sesuoh duorp ,llat dah mahgnittoN fo tsew ehT
.yks deuh-neerg a ekil ,wolga sevael sseltnuoc tes thgilnus ,nihtiw morf tekciht eht gniweiV
.nihc reh gnitfil dna spets reh gnignirps ,reh hguorht delzzif yoj fo elkraps A  ".erus-S"
".ti evael I erehw rebmemer I"
.liat reh fo pit eht morf trid emos detsud ehs ,tegrat eht ot deklaw yeht sA ".yllaer toN"
".oot dnuorg eht no gniyats m'I sseug I nehT"
.htims niatnuom eht
".hgih taht gniog ton m'I"
.kcits gnitniop s'rotut a ekil worra eht dehsiws ehS
,mra sih nwod wob eht gnulf eh
".kcab trats dluohs eW"
.ylimaf ym morf snossel teg I"
nairaM levon gnimocpu eht morf tprecxe na
".sseug I ,trid dna seert otni kcits oT"
.gnol erofeb nwod eb d'eh wenk ehs ,gnitiaW .reh dniheb dekcilf liat reH .spih reh no stsif reh depporp ehS  ".t'now I"
,hguob egral a dniheb morf tuo deppop eH
,mra eno rednu steksab sih htob dekcut
.seniv ylkcirp fo niatruc a edisa peews ot ti desu dna wob sih eerf dellup eH ".tsrif
”nitaL morf eucseR A
".krab eht no tops thgil siht rof gnimia saw I"
".rehto eht fo tnorf ni toof eno tsuj s'tI"
"?siht od ot desoppus I ma woH"
,denethgiarts dot ynwarcs ehT
,hsurbrednu eht hguorht depoort riap ehT  .hcnifdloG
.saw hcnarb eht worran woh ta nwod kool ot ton delggurts ehS
.seirrebkcalb epir fo tekciht a tsniaga llew decnalab rehtieN
.eert dna ,wob ,gnirts dengila taht elgna na gnidnif elbuort dah ehs ,desolc eye eno htiw nevE
,retal tnemom eno ylesicerP
.taehc t'nod uoy nehw uoy sa tsaf sa m'I"
.emit rehtona tekram eht ot reh ekat ot telracS teg dluoc ehS
,notuf a otno fi sa ,hcnarb wol a otno kcab tas eH ".woh
.draytruoc rewol eht fo tnetxe raf eht ta esuohetag lanif dna esuohetag eltsac eht hguorht ssap ot hguone eelg rieht niatnoc ot deganam niboR dna nairaM ,stnahcrem tlas eht dima neddiH  2 fo
ylno er'eW" .tnemesuma ni mih ta detfil worb reH  ".ysae s'tI ?eeS"
".dnuorg eht ffo teef wef a
.sexof eht deteerg edahs looc s'doowrehS
AF ro rettiwT no opmeT wolloF
.ecneitapmi fo tniop eht ot epir fi sa ,ylisae eerf ekorb tI
"?ti ot etulf eritne na gniyt regnol on er'uoY"
".dniheb em evael t'noD"
seires dliW sexiS dna
.seirreb fo rebmun yranidroartxe na eta niboR dna nairaM
,noitibma reh fo deeps eht ta gnivoM  ".uoy tel t'now I"
.uoy ekaw annaw t'ndid I"
~ ~ ~  .doow rediw eht otni kcab yaw rieht edam dna tekciht eht detixe yeht ,rehtegoT
ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.sih nwod detsud liat reH  ".tey
.deggurhs dna kcen sih fo ffurcs eht dehctarcs eh ,lleps a retfA
,bmun gniog mra na fo gninialpmoC
.mih nees tsal d'ehs noitcerid eht ni eltsuh d'ehS
.esrow neve seilf ti ro reggib ti ekam t'nac I"
.gnineve no denepo seye reh
"?esolc gnitteg ew erA"
.tey doog ton s'tI"
.esnes sekam taht esoppus I"
.pu sdray lareves morf reh gnihctaw dna nwod-edispu
.dnim ym ni stsopngis otni meht ekam I oS"
.deye-ediw dna elbatrofmoc ,ssarg eht no delwarps ohw ,niboR ot deppord ezag reH
,enohs seirrebkcalb fo sdnasuoht ,tnemamrif siht tsniaga gnitaolF
".seirreb ynam ees t'nod I"
.seloh dna spmul devrac-ylluferac derutaef hcihw ,ti ot dehsal dor dnoces a dah worra lanoitnevnoc etiuq ehT
2 traP ,nuK'O epmeT yb
,hsurb eht ni steksab deer rieht dehsats gnivaH
~ ~ ~  ".esaelp uoy fi ,yaw sihT"
,dettahc dna deklaw klof desserd-llew ereht dna ereh hguoht
.tsehc ynwarcs s'noinapmoc reh no nihc reh detser nairaM
".thgiarts gniylf s'ti ekil em ot skool tI"
,sseworp laitram sti rof denwoner yldrah elihw ,enilemreH esuoH
.revo ti dednah dna eerf yellov eht deknay eh ,eert eht tsap deklaw yeht sA ".esrow
.mahgnittoN ni seirrebkcalb ynam toN"
"?yrruh ot evah ew oD"
.swalc ytniad htiw eniv eht morf eno dekculp nairaM
.deraos traeh s'nairaM
.drawrof ti tohs dna ,worra eht dekcon
.nihc reh tsniaga srehtaef eht delriwt ehs ,mih no ezag reH
,snoitcudorP tenalPruF yb
.eert eht dehcaer yehT
".gniltserw ta niw syawla uoy woh ekil s'tI"
,ytpme doots sllats eht fo tsom
.sdoow peed eht fo noitcerid eht ni daeh sih detlit dna ,reh ta sgnaf elbaima dehsalf
".gnihctelf suoitatnetso ti evig dluoc uoy spahreP"
.doog etiuq neeb dah thguorb eh seno ehT
"?I t'ndid ,ffo dezod I"
.deppid elzzum gnilims reH
.mih dennip d'ehs semit eht lla fo thguoht ehs sa spil reh dnuof elims A
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer ,nuK'O epmeT yb
".niboR ,no daeL .llew yreV"
".su sehctac enoemos erofeb nwot attuo teg ot evah tsuj ew woN"
.roolf tserof eht no dehsinav dna detcelloc thgilnus fo sloop ,ereht dna ereH
.reviuq eht otni deggurhs eH
.wey egral eht otni tib ti erofeb repip dedneffo na ekil gnikeirhs elissim sti ,degnawt wob ehT
.ecnalg a mih tsac ehS
.ecnarussaer eltneg htiw sdnah reh deppirg eH  "?llaf I fi tahW"
.modeerf sih dneirf reh deivne xof elbon gnuoy eht ,rethgual dna yreneerg fo dlrow a ni deltseN
.eman yb sregnis eht ot reh decudortni eH
.htaerb ydaets a htiw ti delevel dna kcab worra eht dellup eH
.elzzum nwo sih otni seirreb gnivohs neewteb ni
.reviuq sih ni tfahs eht dehsats eh ,lufhsab egnit a gnidnuoS ".ton
,dessap tnemom teiuq A
.ti otno pu reh luah ot mih dettimrep dna dehgis ehs ,thgieh reh flah eb ot dnuorg ot hcnarb morf ecnatsid eht gnigduJ
,wollip retteb on gnidniF
.sepahs tnereffid era seert ehT"  ".syawlA"
.dnah reh gnidloh llits ,erom ecno dnuorg eht ot decnuob dna eert eht morf deppord eh
.drawrof pets suoituac a koot ehS
.dekrow nalp ruoY"  ".ti edam eW"
.meht yfitnedi ot mih rof hguone devorp seton fo hctits trohs a tsuj nevE
.dewollof ehS .woregdeh nettogrof-gnol a ni eloh elbisivni-raen a hguorht dekcud niboR
.neerg dna htworg yb decalper ,yawa llef noitatibahni dna yrtsudni fo stnecS
.niaga ffo elbmarcs d'eh ,yponac eht fo thgil gnitfihs eht ekil ,nehT
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.worg ot erom egaruocne ot seert ekat ot woh dna nehw gniwonk
.reh gnidnuorrus srebmit eht deyevrus nexiv gnuoy ehT
.desuap nexiv gnuoy eht
”nitaL morf eucseR A“
".ereh meht tae ot evah ll'ew nehT"
.eltsac eht fo sdeen dnaldoow eht gnissucsid nehw od rehtaf sih nees d'ehs erutseg a :nihc sih dekorts eh ,deworran seyE
.sredluohs reh dnuora ti deppils niboR
.redluohs sih otno kcab wob sih gnuls eh ,no gnidaeL ".ylimaf
.gums elzzum ,dessorc smra
.esuoh cilbup a morf deohce etul fo sniarts teews sa hctiwt yrrem a liat ,deggurhs dot gnuoy ehT ".dekrow
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.seniv ni meht gnihtaws ,egattoc nwodelbmut a dna seert egral nezod a nekatrevo dah tI
.fael nwolbdniw a ekil decnad eh ereh tub
,yaD nuS a gnieb tI
.hguob eht gnola dekcab dna reh htiw seye dekcol eh ,sih htiw sdnah reh htob gnidloH
.daeh reh koohs dna spoteert eht ta decnalg ehS
.tserof eht otni repeed derutnev yeht sa edis sih ta deklaw ehS
.taht ekil skool tsuj tI"
".eltsihw rellams a devrac uoY"
.elbmarb fo elgnat evissam a ot emac yeht ,edis rehto eht nO
,gnola knils ot ton tseb sih gniod eb ot deraeppa niboR
.smra reh dessorc nairaM ,no dort yeht sA
".aedi doog a s'tahT"
.eciohc suoregnad a neeb dah sreppilS
.troffe fo tnap a tuohtiw lla
.hsif a ekil miws dluoc ehs ,eporuE ni esuoh elbon yreve fo senil ylimaf eht eziromem ot evah t'ndid ehs fi spahreP .gol
)nairaM levon gnimocpu eht fo tprecxe na(
.hceeps lamrof reh detatimi eh ,gniraeb ykeehc sih gniniageR
.sdribgnos fo sdnuos eht hctac ot deleviws srae deppit-kcalb siH
".ees dna em dniheb dnatS"
.hgih…tib a sdnuos osla tI"
".ecnalab ot liat ruoy esU"
.swap reh ni revo worra eht denrut nexiv gnuoy ehT
.don yhs a reh evag eH
".uoy eveileb I tuB"
.yreneerg fo eltsur teiuq eht yb dekram
.pu hctac ot eganam d'ehs ,tsal tA
.mih ta gnilims flesreh dnuof ehS
.steksab sih fo eno no deer esool a ta dekcip dna edirts eldi hcae htiw tuo sgel sih dekcik eh ,ralucitrap ni erehwon gnikooL ".mahgnittoN
.elims teews a meht dehsalf nairaM retfa tsael ta ,dnim elttil meht diap sevlesmeht stnahcrem ehT
.dneirf reh morf ytsedom fo rekcilf siht deiduts dnim enipluv reh ,emit tsrif eht rof toN
".og uoy hgih woh rettam on emas eht skrow tI" .deggurhs eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.yawa llup ot evom on edam eh tub
.tabmoc demranu fo scisab eht ni nerdlihc sti deniart gnol dah
".eltsihw eht fo esuaceb devruc tI"
.tekram yaD nrutaS eht fo elgnatcer enotselbboc ediw eht dehcaer sexof eht ,no gnisserP
.sepols ylggarcs pu yaw rieht dekcip dna ,smaerts gniremmilg deppoh
.steksab eht tuoba wonk t'ndid I"
".niboR raed ,em trocse ot dnik yrev era uoY"
.ria-dim pu ti deppans dna yrreb a dessot eh ,liat sih fo hsal yssas a htiW
.hsinav dluow eh ,knilb a ni ,nehT
".dekoorc ylf ti sekam tahT"
.reh ot pu elims gnoledis a dessot eH
.thgiled a neeb dah yeht ,stiurf deillej dna deird ylno fo retniw elohw a retfA
.yb dezeerb taht cipot yreve dna
.dohsnu sdoow eht dnuora nur t'ndid namowelbon a ,sediseB .gnillaf liatne dluow taht tub ,ffo meht gnikat deredisnoc ehS
.kcuts dah ti erehw fo thgir eht ot hcni na tops a ot detniop eh ,worra eht eerf gnillup retfA
.tsrif edistuo eht no seno eht tae sdriB"
.tnemom a rof tcatnoc eye ekorb eh sa nwod ylyhs dekcilf srae siH
.epir yrev era seirreb esehT"
.noitcepsni reh rof tuo ti dleh neht ,mlap sih otni noitseuq ni tfahs eht dekcilf dna kcab dehcaer eH
.weiv retteb a rof kcor a otno debmilc neht
,edirp htiw dekrims yob ehT
".hguoht ,kcas a thguorb I"
,yad eht fo ytuaeb eht ,erutnev rieht fo ecnellecxe eht tuoba derettahc dna htrae eht no sevlesmeht detaes stik xof owT
.duol yrev t'nsi tI" .deddon eH
".yawyna ,seno hserf toN"
.yad yreve siht ekil evil dluoc eH
.seiduts reh ni deretnuocne d'ehs gnihtyna htiw rap no
.wob elttil taen a evag eh sa hsiruolf a htiw pag eht detneserp dnah eerf siH
,d'F yllarutluC ta retirw ffats eht si ohw ,nuK'O epmeT yb
.etsahtsop htuom reh otni ti fo tser eht pop ot dah ehs os
~ ~ ~  .tnemom a rof seye reh desolc ehS
.ecnatsid eht esolc ot reh rof detiaw eh sa ruf sih morf krab fo stib gnikcilf
.ton m'I"  ".gnikoj er'uoY"
..htims niatnuom eht
.ecnad luferac dna wols a ni knurt eht ot kcab neht
.reh ta tuo dekop eugnot knip siH ".ton m'I"
.ffur keehc sih dnuora reep ot mih dniheb deppils ehS
".hpmyn dnaldoow a ekil er'uoY
.levon htgnel-lluf eht fo esaeler eht no setadpu rof
".rehtruf hcum taht ton s'tI .nom'C"
,hcnarb rewol a ot gnuws eh ,noitom diulf a ni ,nehT .dellor seye neerg thgirb siH
.seert fo xim eht hguorht yaw reh dekcip nairaM
.ffo seerged wef a ti dah eh spahreP
.retnec daed ,detarbiv dna eert a otni degdew neht ,dribgnos lacainam a ekil dehceercs tI
".snossel dah I esuaceb s'tahT"
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht saw sihT
,mih no seye yal ot gniyrt ,nups ehS "!yeH"
.egailof fo elppir eht dima ereht dna ereh yks fo sespmilg eht dehctaw dna ssarg eht no kcab yal yehT
.txen ecudorp dluow niboR ytisoiruc tahw wenk reven enO
.dessap yeht sa lezah a ot ecnatniauqca ni deddon eH ".sepahs
.hcniffahC .liatgaW etihW
,sdoow eht otni lleW
".steksab eht thguorb ev'dluohs eW"
.ekal dlareme na fo ecafrus eht ekil ezeerb eht ni delppir sevael fo yponac eht ,evobA
.eciuj htiw gnimmirb sduolc mrots krad
.eerf worra eht dellup neht ,noitatiseh ni delffuhs eH ".haeY"
.wob dna reviuq a tuo debbarg dna pmuts wolloh a otni dehcaer eh ,edirts gnikaerb tuohtiW ".yawflah ebyaM"
.srae sih deppid dna demriuqs dot ehT
,sregnif reh otno gninnur detrats eciuj nehT
.erac lufhsab ylno ,ecnereverri ron egufretbus rehtien dleh enot siH ".uoy
".edisni og attog ev'eW"
,niarb eht fo gninoh elbaredisnoc a koot retserof a gnieb taht flesreh ot dekramer ehs ,emit tsrif eht rof toN
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
".hguoht ,dnuorg eht no talf er'yeht nehw dnif ot drah era sworrA .ebyaM"
.rebmit nellaf dna htworgrednu fo rennam lla ssapyb ot mih dewolla dohtem ehT
”nitaL morf eucseR A“
".yad a ni sgniht derdnuh a yduts ot evah t'nod tsuj I"
.ssenteews hcir fo yarps a ni tsrub yrreb ehT
,meht etatimi ot hguone hcir stnahcrem eht dna ,selboN
.eltsac eht fo srewot eht neve ees regnol on dluoc ehs ezilaer ot ylno ,kcab dekool dna esir a detserc nairaM
.htrae eht ot tsal ta dna ,erom wef a neewteb deppoh
teews siht ni tnemtnetnoc reh ot dedda reh gnigguh dneirf tseb reh tub ,ti tuoba mih desaet evah d'ehs ,txetnoc rehtona nI
.reh ta esor srae siH ".won tsuj dessim I"
.moor erom reh evig ot pu dekcab eH ".dooG"
,snoitareneg rof dnaldoow siht gnidnet neeb dah sdooH ehT
.yrreb rehtona otni tib ehs ,noitaredisnoc ekilydal htiW ".epir
.ecnelis feirb sih ekorb eh ,retal spets wef A .deddon niboR
"?yaw taht wob ruoy esol ll'uoy deracs uoy t'nerA"
.noitom eht detartsulli dnah sih fo peews detareggaxe nA
.hgual a delfits dna smra reh dessorc ehS
.tnemom deniats-yrreb tahwemos dna
.sevlesmeht fo weiv detalfni tsom eht dessessop mahgnittoN ni ohw no sgnisum sih ni deremmats dot gnuoy ehT
.niboR ot denrut ehs sa thgiled ni pu deppop srae reH
.ehportsatac gnignirb tuohtiw dewollof pets rehtonA
.doohrobhgien railimaf a hguorht fi sa deklaw noinapmoc reh tub ,reh ot sselkcart demees llits tI
.drow etanro eht ta nirg a htiw tuo gnurps sreksihw siH
,tuo dehsub liat siH
.elap dna esraps stiurf eht dnuof tub ,nwod dna pu tekciht eht dekool ehS  "!ereh er'eW"
yrots s’yadot dna
.navarac llams eht fo daeha derepmacs dna snoinapmoc gnilevart elihwtsre rieht ot eybdoog dib yeht ,esuohetag lanif eht fo thgis fo tuo ecnO
.tuo sdray ytnewt spahrep ,eert egral a ta demia dna niaga worra eht dekcon niboR ".tfel gnimia m'I
".seert eht otni pu kcab gniylf uoy pots ot uoy fo dloh peek ot evah ll'I dnatsrednu uoY"
.ni dekcud ehs ,egailof depard eht gnidiovA
.enot sih morf gnillaf erusopmoc eht ,elims elttil a reh tsac eH
.sreh htiw rehto eht depool neht dna
skeerc eht ni elbbow t'ndluow skcor hcihw wenk eH
,reh erofeb doots eH
?reh htiw lerdnuocs a eb ot tegrof tub ,yad gnol eht lla keehc fo emotipe yrev eht eb eh dluoc woH
.daeh reh koohs nexiv gnuoy ehT
.reh ot ti dereffo dna reviuq sih dnuora morf gab savnac ytpme na deitnu eh ,raeg sih gniddehS ".steksab
.eugnot reh no deregnil seirreb fo etsatretfa tsetniaf ehT
".tnorf eht no eltsihw eht tup dluoc uoy ,eno evah t'ndid ti fI"
.tsehc niht sih devaeh hgis A  ".hgih…tib
.enihsnus ekil enohs elims siH
,peews ysae elgnis a htiW ".duol
.seldnac dna snekcihc fo ecirp eht revo delggah stnavres rieht elihw
,pets desiop a htiW
.mih ot dnah a dednetxe ehs ,gnidnatS ".gnihtoN"  "?tahW"
.dnah sih dednetxe neht
.reviuq sih otni dna redluohs sih revo dekeep ehs ,tnorf taht nO
eht nI  .enadnum dna taerg srettam tuoba gnippay llits ,yltfos reh dleh eH
.teksab gnittink degatobas ylhsidneif a fo tnelaviuqe evitategev eht eb ot dekool hcihw ,htworgrevo eht ta detniop eh ,gnikcilf liat sih htiw ediseb gnidnatS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.noisicerp etaciled htiw bmoc nedoow a fo hteet eht was esuom stfarc a hctaw ot wodniw pohs a ni dereep ehs ,seot reh no gnidnatS
.dlo sraey dnasuoht a spmuts morf gnarps sknurt yldnipS
.spart erom hguoht ,seitilibisnopser rewef spahrep dleh siutrepelliM eltsaC s'ylimaf reH
.efas yllohw tlef ehs ,enihsnus deretlif-fael
:nairaM“   yojne esaelP
,burcs dna nwot hguorht edis reh ta dekih dah niboR
.krowidnah sih enimaxe reh dehctaw eh sa thguoht ni pu dehcnub worb siH
"?daehworra na deen ti seod yhW"
.dribkcalB .ffahcffihC
.tnuocca yrruFoS sih ro
"?eeS" .reh ot denrut eH
.erol ylimaf ot gnidrocca ,stnaliassa ynam fo gniodnu eht devorp dah sselpleh thguoht xof a morf kcattaretnuoc esirprus A
,reh teerg dluow elims siH
.dnoyeb egdirb eht dna nwot fo egde eht drawot reh del eh sa cinut dnahdnoces eht rednu pu deffup tsehc siH
.htuom reh otni ti deppop ehS
.elttil a hsulb reh edam mih htiw eson ot eson gnidnatS
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si
.mra sih dezeeuqs ehs ,noitatiseh tuohtiW  "?terces a wonk annaW"
llafdniW eht fo retirw eht dna
"?worra gniltsihw ruoy taht sI"
nellaf a revo deppoh ehS ".esnes
,seirreb nezod a retfA
,evren sih deniager eh neht tuB
.woh uoy wohs nac I"
,tnemirrem elbaredisnoc htiW
".uoy fo doog yreV"
.mra sih koot dna denrut ehs ,llab lager a ta ydal nrobhgih a fo esiop eht lla htiW
.daeha dnaldoow eht ot ediug fo tros yna sa meht fo daeha stsopngis dairym eht ees ot deirt neht ,ni noiton siht koot nairaM  ".spleh tI
.moor gnittis s'eno ni gnieb fo esae eht htiw ,hcnarb a morf gnilgnad ro gol dlo emos no detaes eb syawla d'eH
.ti morf llihnwod llor thgim taht rodnelps yna gnihctac fo epoh eht ni sllaw eltsac eht dnoyeb tsuj devil
.raeg gnitoohs fo noitcudorp neddus sih ta derettit ehS
.seert dekcap-esolc eht neewteb gnippoh hsalf ytsur a eb tsuj d'eh ,retfaerehT
"?ssim reven uoy emoc woH"
.sdnah sih otni kcab worra eht decalp dna deddon lrig ehT