.uoy gnidloh peek tsuj d'I os ,yrrac ot ysae yllaer er'uoY .hO"  ".niboR ,su oT"
.snedrag breh teksab elttil dna nogaw erutainim htiw etelpmoc
.eugnot sih tuo kcuts eH ".hu-
.esuohetag eht otni mih dellup ehs sa tnialpmoc on edam eH
”nitaL morf eucseR A“
.ria eht otni thgiarts mra na kcuts eH
.noitautis rieht fo kcots koot dna dnuora dekool nexiv gnuoy ehT ".retteb
,d'F yllarutluC ta retirw ffats eht si ohw
,noitnetta ta doots eH
".enog er'uoy wonk neve t'now yehT"
.yaw tnereffid rehtegotla na ni derettulf traeh deretsulf ydaerla reH ".elbissopmi
.eciov sih deretne ytilimuh eraR
,rewot dnarg eht ot spets eht no tas namowelbon erah A
.tew llits ylsuolucarim t'nsaw ti erus ekam ot walc a htiw tolb kni taerg eht debbad ylevixelfer neht ,ti otni deirruh ehS
".sehtolc egnahc em tel tub
.deb reh fo tsop a dnuora flesmih gnuws eH ".laed
.yvaeh os si deb ruoy eveileb t'nac I"
".yawllah eht otni deppets I sa noos sa ereh ni kcab em dnes dluow telracS"
.rewot eht ot esolc kcuts nairaM ,lausac tiag reh gnipeeK ".ereht
.taht od reven d'I wonk uoY"
.llewkni s'eno rof noitatnedni taht dah sksed pal yhw denrael ehs nehw gniraew neeb d'ehs sserd eht debbarg ehs ,ebordraw reh fo kcab eht ot gniggiD
.gnillaf ydaerla erew yeht detsisni hcamots reH
.liat ynwarcs sih fo kcilf a htiw reh ta smra sih desiar eH
.reh thguac eh erofeb pilf a flah rof emit dah ylno hcamots reH
".og s'tel dna sehtolc ecin-ton emos no tup oS"
.rehgih elttil a smra sih detfil eH ".nwo
.nalp elbirret sih ot eud eltsac a fo edis eht ffo detemmulp yeht fi trocse ylnameltneg a ekil reh otno dloh d'eH
,strac rieht dekcap stnahcrem nezod a flaH
eht morf epor eht teg ot deen ot gniog er'ew os ,rewot ruoy no kcab si epor doog s'dad yM .yakO"
"!eton a gnivael m'I"
".on dlot gnieb morf peek ot gniyrt er'eW
"?won od ew od tahW"
.flesreh rof erom owt koot dna owt mih dednah ehS ".steksab eseht dloh ew rO"
.rewot erauqs eht fo renroc eht dnuora meht deppihw eh ,droc fo teef elpuoc rehtona tuo gnitteL ".yawyna
.sespalloc nwot elohw eht dna mahgnittoN rednu klahc fo eceip yreve pu esu uoy sekam telracS litnu ereh yats nac uoy rO"
,meht tes d'ehs naht rehtruf neve denethgiarts srae siH
.seye sih fo llor citegolopa na dereffo eH
uoy erA" .tnatsni na ni desuap eH
.deb reh no telbat eht tes dna denaorg nexiv gnuoy ehT
,neeL reviR eht ,mahgnittoN
.ralloc cinut sih denethgiarts ehs ,ti ta saw ehs elihW .liat sih dekcutnu dna srae sih pu denrut ehs nehT
.sdnalsi elttil eht ot nwod ,dnim reh ni pam eht erutcip ot deirt ehS ".dnaltehS morf si telracS"
".guj wen a ekorb I fi ssorc eb dluow muM" .deggurhs eH  .woh erus ton
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,nuK'O epmeT yb )nairaM
.seye reh dellor nairaM
.niboR sa nwonk retteB
".rallec toor s'enoemos ni yalp nac ew ebyam nehT"
.retserof eltsac eht fo nos
.drager rednet htiw sreh tem seye neerg siH
".wodniw eht tuo tif t'nac deb ruoY"
.gnorw gnihtyna gniod t'nsaw ehs dezilaer neht
,talf srae ,wol kcab
".ot desoppus m'I tahw gniod ecitcarp evah yllautca I ,uoy ekilnu dnA"
.delggig neht ,ssecnirp elat yriaf a ekil denoows ehS ".oreh yM"
"?ereh morf nwod teg ew od woH"
,moor eht otni remmus derrits ezeerb tfos A
.mih htiw reh gnillup ,emarf wodniw eht dnoyeb deppets eh dna elzzum sih depacse erutnevda fo pay llams A "!eerhT .owT .enO"
.ynnus yllaicepse mees did rehtaew ehT
.selit fo wor tsal eht ffo detoocs nairaM
".kcab og dluohs eW"
".gnikool m'I tub ,tey yna nees t'nevah I"
hguoht ,dethgils tlef ehS "?guj dlo nA"
.pissog htiw gnihctiwt sliat rieht
".elbon a m'I ,sediseb dnA"
".ereh thgir era sriats ehT"
.ria nepo eht otni wodniw eht tuo dnah a kcuts xof nommoc ehT
.noitautis latnoziroh erom raf a ni reh gnitrofmoc fi sa
.nwod bmilc nac I kniht t'nod I"
".kaerb yeht nehw ni seno wen tup I os ,seno eraps eht peek yeht erehw wonk I .selit foor emos esool kconk uoy fi yrrow t'noD"
.ria nepo otni ffo delgnad liat reh sa mih dnuora depparw sgel dna smra
,sregnif reh gnicalretnI
.dehgis nexiv gnuoy ehT  ".epor thguorb I"
.ecnahc riaf a dah yeht ,setag eht laes ot nwod pollag t'ndid ,telracS ,diamesrun reh gnimussA .ereht ydoboN
".esnes sekam tahT"
".diamdnah erutainim reh er'uoy dnA"
dneirf tseb a sa dooH niboR gnivah woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
".ereht uoy teg ll'I dna og annog er'ew yaw hcihw em llet tsuJ .yako s'tI"
.delbmurc dna dekcarc ti ,ereht dna ereH
.reporp eltsac eht fo thgil eht otni degreme yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.htims niatnuom eht
,dooH dranyeR gnuoy fo lavirra eht decnuonna troffe fo tnurg tfos a dna enots no swalc fo ffucs A
.draytruoc eht ot wodniw eht morf decnalg eh ,mlac lausac htiW
.diam yrellucs tar eht detcepsus ehs ,gnilbmurg eht fo erbmit eht morF
.rehtruf yna og t'ndluoc ti litnu dnah rehto sih fo sregnif eht hguorht regnif xedni na dekop eH ".deppots
.detfil sreksihw htiw rethgiarts elttil a pu tas neht ,htaerb wols a tuo tel ehS ".gnitiaw-
".sehsub eht fo dnats gib siht tuoba wonk I
.gnihtemos htiw dellif feihcrek a decudorp eh ,tleb sih ot gnihcaeR .dekniw eH ".huh-
.meht no gniworg srewolf evah t'nod snosirP
.wodniw eht tuo thgiarts dekool eh sa neve ,deleviws srae siH "?ereht kcab gniyduts uoy erA"
.eltsac eht dnuora trad ot deunitnoc ezag s'niboR
.hcamots reh no eldnub eht decalp eH
"?neht deneppah ev'dluow tahW"
,htaerb peed a htiW
.elims gnisaet a mih tsac ehs
.ynnin a ekil gniremmats pu dniw d'ehs ,tneserp mih htiw hcum oot ti tuoba thguoht ehs fi
.noitcejbo ton hguoht ,noitatiseh htiw reh ot decnalg eH ".krow
.nehctik eht fo pot eht ot rewot eht fo tnorf eht dnuora htap wercskroc ytnuaj a decnuob teef erab siH
".reverof nitaL gniyduts neeb ev'uoY"
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     ~ ~ ~  ".em
.wodniw eht fo sedis eht yb flesmih thguac dna smra sih tuo dehcterts eh ,kcab ylsselkcer gnikcoR ".nairaM ,nom'C"
,mih dehctulc dna dekaeuqs ehS "!raed hO"
.noitisop suoiracerp rieht fo reh gnidnimer ,sih tsniaga liat reh welb ezeerb dlim A
,eniF" .pu tas ehs
.tog reve erutsop sih sa elbatcepser sa tuoba otni kcab mih denethgiarts dna redluohs sih debbarg nairaM  .dekcut liat
rewot eht fo esab eht ta gniworg sesor eht fo tnecs teews ehT
.sdleihs yldneirf ekil erom dna sraeps elitsoh ekil ssel dekool steparap llaw eht hguoht
.rewot ot esuohetag morf ,nosrep ot nosrep morf dekcilf seye neerg
.elkcuhc a htiw daeh reh koohs ehS  ".ysaE"
.yponac yfael a hguorht nus eht ekil seye neerg sih ni delkraps
.flesreh dednimer ehs ,yduts dna moor reh ni yats ot detcurtsni saw ehS
.deppots ev'dluow tI"
.ytisoiruc dna tsurt htiw desuap eh tub ,ezag sih deworran euqip dliM
.yteixna ni tuo dehsub liat reH ".seY"  "?ydaeR
,koob egral a revo dehcnuh xof llams A  2 fo
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.stnavres rehto s'eltsac eht fo yna naht ssel selbon was ylimaf sih taht semitemos togrof ehS ".sdiamdnah
.sih ni dnah reh decalp tub ,noicipsus yrw fo kool a mih tsac ehs ,dnuorg eht ot ecnatsid taerg eht nwod gnireep niagA
.wodniw eht ecaf ll'I"
.sserd lacirtemmysa reh denethgiarts ehs ,seohs reh otni gnippoH
".nwod naht redrah tol a si pU"
.ygrene tneitapmi htiw htrof dna kcab dehsiws hcihw ,liat sih rof evas
".dlohesuoh erutainim doog a eb dluow ti dediced ytsejaM reH ,eltsac erutainim a ekil si peek eht ecniS"
".uoy naht rekaens retteb a m'I tub ,llaw eltsac a bmilc ot woh wonk ton yam I"
.deifilpma dna deohce spetstoof rieht
".draytruoc eht ni dnal ot snoegip fo hcnub a teg dluoc ew ,sbmurc daerb emos teg ew fi ebyaM .kooh gnilpparg a sa esu ot gnihtemos deen ot gniog er'ew dnA .llew
,yaled a flesreh thguob ehs
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.dewots esidnahcrem rieht fo tsal eht gniees
".uoy eveileb I .eniF"
.sdiamdnah eb t'nac selboN"
,sehtolc nwod-em-dnah dna ruf ytsur fo ssem A  ".niboR olluH"
.ereht pu skoob ym lla evael em dah uoY"
.sriats eht nwod dekluks mrof ynniks siH ".sseug
,tem yeht ecnis sraey ruof eht nI
,kcik lanif a htiW
.sffur keehc reh rednu dewolg hsulb A
.feihcsim fo regnibrah a eb ot elims taht denrael dah ehs
".ereht llams era sesroh eht llA"
,epor eht thgit gnidloH ".siht ekiL
,htaerb peed a htiW
.dnah sih koot ehS ".no emoC"
.sreksihw eht fo tlit elbaffa na htiw stnemegnarraer reh detarelot niboR
".nitaL erom snaem ti esuaceb esrow tub ,diamdnah a ekil s'tahT" .deddon eH ".thgiR"
.raef gnitapissid reh hguorht ekorb elggig A
.tnuocca yrruFoS sih ro ytiniffAruF sih no
.trap tsrif eht retfa reisae stol steg tI
.etag tnorf eht tuo klaw ot gniog er'eW"
.enorht eht rof enil ni txen si edialedA ssecnirP dnA"
.epor siht fo hcni yreve detset I"
neek siH .ytivitca eht deiduts dneirf reH
,walc a morf trid yranigami gninaelC ".esaelp
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer ,nuK'O epmeT yb
.regnif xedni reh gnisiar yb tniop sih koot nairaM ,dednetni sa sriats eht nwod gnippetS
,edahs looc eht otni deppets yeht sA
.htuom sih otni seirreb eht fo rehtona dessot dna woble na htiw reh degdun eH ".wodniw eht ni kcab bmilc nac eW"
".mahgnittoN rof tuo gnikool tsuj m'I"
.roolf a sa llaw eht fo kniht tsuJ"
.llis wodniw eht no kcab degde eh ,mra eno dnuora epor eht gnilioC
".uoy eucser ot emac I yhw s'tahT"
.sseug I ,ydobyreve tsap kaenS .onnuD"
.reffo eht etaicerppa od I"
.enil thgiarts a otni werd htuom reH .yawa dekool ehS
.yoj htiw htrof dna kcab deffulf liat yffurcs tahT
seires dliW sexiS dna
.delacs tsuj d'ehs srewot ynam woh rettam on ,gnitiaw-ni-ydal neeuq erutuf a tifeb ton dluow tahT
.ybsressap tab yadnoon rof tuo gnikool yletuloser llits tub ,gnitegdif mih dewohs dneirf reh ta kool kciuq A
.nwo sih neve ro thgiew reh yb detceffanu demees eH
.srotsecna daed-gnol dna selttab tneicna fo sgnignah llaw eht gnisserac
.wodniw eht ot despiart eH ".wodniw
.snoisnelced ralugerri fo elbat a revo gnirop
.em tsurT .lliw eW"  "!retteb d'eW"
".meht nees ev'I .egalliv eht ni evil nerdlihc rehtO .niboR"
.teef sih ot decnuob eh ,emarfdeb eht fo kaerc a htiW "!seY"
".emit a ta pets a gniog ylno er'ew tub ,haeY"
".sdoow eht ni gniyalp ton ,gniyduts eb ot tnaem m'I"
.nihc sih dehctarcs eH
:nairaM“   yojne esaelP
".em fo og tel t'noD"
.laed gib a s'taht yhw ees t'nod I"
.spih reh no depporp stsif reH ".niboR"
.rennam gnimrahc a ni demaelg sgnaf ylraep siH ".em
"?keep t'now uoy wonk I od woH"
,deraeppa elzzum dereksihw-yffurcs railimaf a ,retal tnatsni nA
.rethgit mih dezeeuqs ehS
,tnatsni na rof thgiarts tohs erutsop siH
.ot desoppus er'ew sgniht gniod er'ew ekil kool ot deen tsuj eW
.krow annog si nalp ruoy kniht t'nod I"
.roolf eht ot gnirettulf repap a ekil yranarg rewol hcum eht fo foor eht ot deppoh niboR
.draytruoc s'peek eht gnillif nedrag breh hsul eht ot sknaht ,llah dlo eht fo tuo emoc dah ohw ees t'ndluoc ehS
.mih dniheb pord peets eht rof drager on htiw dehcrep eH
".t'now I esimorp I" .dezzirf liat siH
.meht rof tnaem sdog eht ecafrus a no erom ecno dednal seohs reH
".yalp ot tuo emoc uoy sekam taht fI !eruS"
.eciov reh deretne mrala thgilS
".gnibburcs ssel tuB"
.nepo derettalc rood a
levon gnimocpu eht fo tprecxe na(
.od stnahcrem esoht nehw evael ew fi su eciton neve t'now ylbaborp sdraug ehT"
.ezeerb eht no pu detfird
".emit eht lla taht yas uoY"
".ees t'now yb gniylf stab yna erus ekaM"
.ti htrow eb retteb seirreb esehT"
”nitaL morf eucseR A“
.tsrif srae ,pu pop mih ees ot emit ni tsuj revo dekool ehS
.tnemnroda wen a droc nat nwolbdniw eht
.yks eulb tfos a tsniaga yb detaolf sduolc etihw yldneirF
,gniod er'ew tahw sksa enoyna fI
.sehsram s'noitan eht fo pam a dekool llits sserd eht flah ,gnibburcs s'telracS lla roF
llafdniW eht fo retirw eht dna
.mih no llef ezag reH
.huh-hU"  "?doog retaerg eht rof si em gnitcartsid oS"
.gij yletirps a ni rewot eht fo edis eht desrevart dot gnuoy ehT
.sdoow eht ni ti dnuof I fi ebirb a ton s'tI"  "?em gnibirb yB"
.mih ecaf ot nups ehs ,sserd reh gninethgiarts dehsinif yawflaH
.erus t'nsaw ehs ,reh yfirtep dluoc wodniw moordeb reh tuo taht ot ralimis os weiv a woH .reh
,eciov sih ot denruter enot luferac tahT
.su raeh annog si telracS .duol os eb t'noD"
".elbuort ni em teg ot gniog er'uoY"
.niboR htiw sdoow eht ni klaw I
.tsehc sih ot ecaf reh desserp ehS
.foor eht fo egde eht morf mih ta nwod dereep ehs ,gnilgnad sgeL
,snoitcudorP tenalPruF yb
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
,wodniw a tuo yawflah dehcrep fo daetsni ,dnuorg dilos no gnidnats neeb d'eh fi sa detooferus sA
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,seirreb eht fo tsal eht gnihsinif yB
.deggurhs eH  "?raf woH"
.reh was eh nehw pu til seye neerg sih ,wodniw eht fo mottob eht ta dessorc smrA
.ereh pu bmilc uoy emit yreve yalp emoc t'nac I"  ".yalp og s'teL"
.ni deppart er'uoy rewot siht ni pu morf ,haeY"
.gnirob era sdik rehto ehT"
.nwo rieht no ekorb esoht fo emoS"
.teprac eht no depmots toof sih dna
,sehtolc sih gnilppir dniw eht ot tnereffidnI  "!deracs m'I"
.derekcins lrig ehT
.epor hcum taht evah t'ndid daD"
"?naem taht s'tahW"
".sehtolc ecin ym niur ot tnaw t'nod tsuj I"
,emas eht dekool epacsdnal rediw ehT
"?oot daeh ym no koob a ecnalab I dluohS"
".sees ydobemos erofeb ,nom'C"
dehcterts nexiv eht ,no dnats ot gnihtemos gnivah ta trofmoc taerg gnikaT  ".erehT"
".seirrebkcalb kcip ot tuo gniog er'ew meht llet
.wap reh gnidloh llits ,reh ediseb decnarp eh ,noitavresbo sih fo duorP
".hctam t'nod meht fo emos nosaer eht erew uoy nwonk evah dluohs I"
.tohsrae nihtiw t'nsaw noitseuq ni retto eht gnikcehc fi sa ,dnuora dekcilf ezag s'niboR ".draugydob
.ffirdim sih dnuora mra na deppils ehs ,suovreN
.draugydob erutainim reh snialpxE"
.roiretxe enots erab eht tsniaga ti tes dna kcab toof a dekcilf eh
.telbat etals no-delbbircs ylluferac reh fo noitcerid eht ni deb eht otno depmohw dnah siH  ".reffo
.enihsnus eht ni tniopeldeen fo pooh a ta gnikrow
.kniw a htiw mih erofeb nups neht ,edirts lausac a dengief ehs ,dnah hcae ni eno htiW ".etag
,draytruoc eht ssorcA
.wodniw eht ecaf ot ydob sih gnuws eh ,gur eht no toof eno gnitnalP
".em htiw pu peek tsomla nac uoY"
.esuohetag peek eht edistuo deggas steksab deer fo kcats a gninimaxe htiw flesreh deisub nairaM
.epor eht no pirg doog a dah I"
"?deirram er'ew naem taht seoD"
,deirrow tub ,taht ekil reh ta dekool eh taht dekil ehS
.sregnif sih neewteb tsud gnitluser eht debbur dna ocserf eht ta dekop eH
"?yawa teg t'nac uoy oS ?yawyna peek dlo eht ni ssecnirP eht dna uoy tup yeht d'yhW"
".gnitiaw-ni-ydal a m'I"
".nwod raf yllaer s'tahT"
.mih edisgnola deb eht otno denilcer lrig ehT
".esaelp ,taht ekil yatS .erehT"
nairaM levon gnimocpu eht morf tprecxe na
".uoy naht erom shgiew taht guj dlo na htiw ffilc eht no tuo siht detset I
.ecarg s'ssecnirP eht fo noitcarf a tsael ta saw depoh ehs tahw htiw draytruoc llams eht ta kcab deppit wap reH ".dlohesuoh
.reh ot dehcaer dna ezeerb eht ni doots eh ,nirg eguh a htiW
.tiurf epir ,teews eht gnoma on yas ot nosaer on dnuof tub
.seirrebkcalb elprup-thgindim fo lluf ti dnif ot eldnub eht denepo ehS
.detcesretni sksat owt eht revenehw dog dniw eht ot depirg dna ,steksab gniwonniw htiw taehw morf ffahc eht koohs ,yrdnual gnuh stnavreS
.niaga seye reh gninepo otni nairaM dexaoc htaed reh ot gnillaf fo kcal eht dna ecarbme ydaets sih ni gnihtemoS
.sretserof eht fo nos eht htiw tnavalag ot reh dezirohtua t'ndah telracS
.seye reh dellor ehS  ".nairaM iH"
.esruoc fo ,hturt eht gnillet saw eH
".erehwon fo neeuq eht er'uoy dnA .erehwon fo gnik eht m'I"
".stab gnipeep rof hctaw tsuJ"
.oot eb dluohs sdoow eht ni seno eht neht ,epir era esuoh eht yb seno eht fi dnA" .deggurhs eH ".sdoow
.meht od I ecno revo era serohc ym tub ,haeY"
,seye sih dellor dot gnuoy ehT
.yawyna trap doog eht si sihT
.mra rehto sih ffo yllanif dna ,kcab sih dniheb neht ,mra eno dnuora ti dils epor eht htiw enod d'eh tsiwt ynnuf ehT ".su
.llaw rewot reehs eht nwod decnalg ehS
sih ni revo meht denrut dna steksab nevow eht detpecca eh ,reh ecaf ot gninnipS
.thgit gnurw ydob reh fo elcsum yrevE
".meht rednu edih annog er'ew fi seno reggib deen eW…" .swap
ssendnoF .terces taerg a derahs d'eh ekil htrof dna kcab liat sih deppihw dna spih reh desaeler eH "?eeS"
".epor doog s'daD s'tI
.esaelp uoy fi ,tnemom eno rof dnuorg eht no teef ruoy peeK"  ".eno teg dluoc I"
.revo mih dekool dna smra reh dessorc ehS
.moor eht otni flesmih gnulf eh ,lliswodniw eht fo edis rehtie gnippirg sdnaH ".meht
.meht ta dekool ehs regnol eht ralugerri erom worg ot demees sdrow ehT
.ykcoc denrut elims siH
.sdnah sih morf noisnet eht koohs dna epor eht desaeler eh ,selit foor fo wor pot detniop eht gnola recnad a ekil gnispiarT
.eb t'ndluohs uoy gnihtemos ot pu er'uoy kniht ot gniog er'yeht ,dnuora gnikaens uoy ees elpoep fI"
.dnuos gnihsarc taerg a detatimi eH ".sespalloc
.mih retfa delttucs ehs ,elpmaxe sih gniwolloF
.redluohs sih revo cirbaf nrow eht ni ecaf reh deirub ehS "!peE"
.retteb yna gniod er'ew tahw ekil dluow ehs kniht t'nod I"
.thguac htaerb reH .decar traeh reH
,syot s'dlihc a ekil yal draytruoc renni ehT
.ecneitapmi htiw dekcilf liat ynwarcs siH
.pu reh depleh niboR
.mih no deworran ezag reh ,gniwehc llitS  ".raf taht toN"
.kool deyonna na htiw sdnah reh detfil ehS
.esacriats enots eht fo pot eht ta ffucs tfos a htiw dednal dna foor eht fo edis eht revo deppord eh ,taht htiW ".epor
.nirg dekoorc a reh tsac eH
.stsiaw rieht dnuora epor eht depool eH ".taht
".ydaer m'I .llew yreV"
.krow ta ffats eltsac eht fo noitcerid eht ni wap a tpews ehS
.smra reh dessorc ehS
.smra sih daerps eH ".reteiuq yaw m'I .yaw oN"
.mih ta esor srae reH
.llis wodniw eht no tis ot pu delbmarcs eh
.llis wodniw eht no dnats ot gnipael dna tsopdeb reh ot droc eht gnittonk-elpirt ,noitca otni gnarps niboR "!emit tuobA"
.wodniw eht ot dekcilf ezag reH
.sdnah sih fo ruf kcalb eht hguorht selkcunk sih wohs ot hguone thgit droc eht deppirg dnah siH "?erus
.nehctik eht otni kaens ew emit yreve thguac su teg uoy tub ,seY"
.resolc elttil a reh degguh niboR
.reh ot txen deb eht otno tsrif-kcab deppolf eH ".gnirob
.nruter ni dnah reh deppirg eh tub
.nosirp a ton si rewoT esoR ehT"
.erutcurts eht gnibmilc seniv esor ekaseman eht ta kcab detniop ehS ".meht
".yllautneve naelc teg steehsdeb dna sroolF
.hgual a htiw ti xaler ot deirt eh neht
.elzzum reh otni yrreb a deppop ehS
.droc gnilgnad eht no deggut eH ".uoy
.deeps elbanosaernu na ta os did ti dnA
".ereh er'uoy elihw degnahc teg t'nac I" mih ta pu gnuws smra reH  ".gniog teg s'teL"
.teiuq peek ot gniyrt ton er'eW
.em tsurT" .redluohs reh htiw mih depmub ehS
.llew sa stnecs rieht gnirucsbo ylekil ,stnalp eht morf ecnargarf tnasaelp a dekab thgilnus ydaetS
”nitaL morf eucseR A
erofeb delwarps doowrehS tsav dna
.don a ni debbob elzzum derruf-tsur siH  ".ot
!eruS" .ssenippah htiw dehsal liat gnilgnad siH  ".esaelp ,nwoD"
.elzzum reh depacse elkcuhc detartsurf A
".gniyduts ekil dednuos tI"
.meht erofeb ytivitca htiw deltsub draytruoc regral hcum sihT
.koob eht ot ,noitnetta reh ton hguoht ,ezag reh denruter ehS ".ereh
.nirg gib a htiw dnatsthgin reh no ti tes ehs ,eson eht ni mih tih t'ndluow revoc eht os remirp eht gnisolC
.dlohesuoh a nur ot woh wonk ot sdeen ehS
.edis eht dnuora gniog er'eW"
.rewot eht pu decnalg eH  "?rebmemeR"
.ytud no draug a ekil ,kcab sih dniheb delttes sdnah siH
— ".niboR muc sivlis ni olubmA"
,rewot enots etihw eht fo edis reehs eht pu derats ehS
.yawllah dehcra eht fo retsalp eht derevoc snrettap cirtemoeg elpmiS
.sriats fo tes dnoces a dednecsed yeht sa derekcins ehS
.edart doog yrev a toN"
".meht htiw yalp og dluohs uoy os ,ysub m'I tuB"
naorg a htiw kcab deppit daeh siH
..htims niatnuom eht
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadot dna
.daerps smra ynwarcs siH
1 traP ,nuK'O epmeT yb
,tnecsed rieht detrats dah taht eno eht ekilnu ton
.kcab reh dniheb depsalc sdnah htiw mih ta krims ot delriwt neht ,liat reh fo hsiws a htiw mih tsap tpews ehS
".ffilc eht nwod dna llaw eltsac eht revo og ot tnaw t'ndid uoy desirprus m'I"
.elbissopmi er'uoY"
.ni ton ,eltsac eht fo tuo elpoep peek ot desoppus er'yehT
.wodniw reh tuo pord gniyzzid eht deye ehS
"?serohc uoy evig t'nod stnerap ruoY"
.esoprup reh evres dluoc yeht tub ,paeh hsibbur eht rof denitsed ylbaborp ,elttirb dna dlo tib A
.eltsac eht fo tser eht ot peek eht detcennoc taht rodirroc eht nwod dereep ehs
.elzzum sih ot denruter elims eht hguoht
kciuq a tuo dehctarcs dna gar a htiw txet gnitsixe eht tuo debburcs ehs ,telbat reh dna klahc fo eceip a gnibbarG ".ti
.foor eht fo egde eht revo detniop dna selit foor eht nwod detoocs eh ,gnittiS ".ysae s'tahT"
".ti edam ew eveileb t'nac I"
".sriats eht esu t'nod I yhw s'tahT"
".sdnah ym ni drib a hctac nac I"
".tib elttil a evom dluow ti thguoht I
".diamesrun erutainim ruoy dnA"
.tnemesuma sselraef htiw gnimaelg sgnaf ylraep
huN"  ".uoy htiw pu peek yletulosba nac I"
.delgnad yeht sa ,niht oot raf won demees droc ehT
,etals eht morf klahc eht deknay ehS
.tleb sih no droc yvaeh fo lioc a detfeh eH ".yako s'tI"  ".nwod
.tnemesuma htiw dekcilf liat siH
.sllaw eht ta derutseg dna nups eH ".ni
.yob eht no psarg reh denesool tsal ta dna ,rehtona neht ,nwod gel luferac a
.emehcs a gnitcocnoc tbuod on ,denetsil eh sa pu dekrep srae deppit-kcalb esohT
.elbuort ot dael nac
;sraeps rieht no gninael ,esuohetag eht ta doots sdraug owT
:demuser erutsop gniklats dnaldoow sih ,tnatsni na nI
.gnitiaw-ni-ydal s'edialedA ssecnirP m'I .nitaL daer ot elba eb ot deen I"
.rehtona rof llac ot hguone rettib tsuj etsatretfa na gnivael ,eugnot reh ssorca tsrub ssenteews trat fo hsur A