.emosdnah ,reilrae ffo stnap ruoy nekat ev’dluohS“
srae s’yehS hcaer ot gniliaf ton eciov ytsul sih
,selkna sih dnuora ylthgil daenk ylno ot detpo nomiS
”?erutcurts elcsum gnitseretni hcus evah skrahs uoy taht wonk uoy diD“
,tsehc deroloc-maerc sih ta gnihctarcs dna gab sih fo pot no ti gniworht
.ti rednu morf epor fo htgnel a barg ot
,pu dnats yehS depleh nomiS
”.llew sa gnihtemos elttil a od dluoc ew gnikniht saw I ,wonk uoY“
,kcid sih htiw wam s’yehS fo tuo dna ni gnisserp
,snoitca s’nomiS revo tsehc sih ni gnilbbub yrrow thgils eht etipsed ssik sih gninruter ylippah krahs eht
”.pu ti pets annog m’I
,tuo dellup gnivaH
htgnel sih fo erom gnisserp dna
,ti gnidlof ylsuolucitem fo daetsni roolf eht ot ylissem epor eht gnippord
nepo swodniw fo elpuoc a dehsup nomiS
,strohs fo riap esool a no dellup nomiS
,tuhs seye sih gnizeeuqS
.esuoh sih ot kcab tog eh retfa yehS gnitxet ,enohp sih pu dekcip nomiS
.ti no gnilkcus dna nwo sih htiw ti gnimoclew
,ffo yehS gnikrej deppots yllanoitnetni nomiS
hgis a htiw hcamots sih no nwod gniyal
.niaga ssik a ni spil rieht tcennoc ot gnikees
,htaerb ot elba gnieb ylerab retfa
tsehc sih no dnah a decalp dna krahs eht sdrawot denael nomiS
,htraeh desunu eht yb riahc elbatrofmoc a ni denilcer dna
mih rof tsehc sih gnihctarcs yltneg daetsni
egde eht no yehS peek ot redro ni gnitaslup dna gnitarbiv
.retal rof ti gnidracsid
,ni htaerb kciuq a kcus ot ytinutroppo eht koot yehS
.keehc sih ot yaw eht lla toohs ot hguone drah gnimmuc
ylsuoveihcsim dennirg nomiS ".od
.nomiS erusaelp ot gnitnaw
,ylbanoitseuq daeh sih detfil dna
,nif s’yehS dnuora demmurd dna
,ylthgil keehc s’krahs eht dessik dna
ti eldnah nac yehS gniwonk
,mih ot txen ni gnidils dna deb suoicaps sih otni krahs eht gnisae daetsni
,lewot a gnitteg erofeb peek ot
,retfa yltrohs peels ot gnibmuccus dna
,taorht dna wam sih otni rehtruf kcid sih hsup ot nomiS gnitnaw
,kcid nwo sih dna
.yehS no nwod gnippird dna wam s’yehS dna
elppin rednet s’yehS no ssik tsal eno gnitnalp
,shtaerb peed fo elpuoc a ekat ot yehS rof gniwolla
,elims dexaler a htiw daeh sih denrut yehS
,reilrae flesmih rof tes eh lewot a no daeherof sih morf taews fo tib a gnipiw retfA
”.eituc ,gnihtaerb ruoy ecap ot elba eb ll’uoy tsurt I“
,gnisaet s’aneyh eht rednu demriuqs dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,deb eht rednu ti denethgit dna
hctorc sih gnidiova yllanoitnetni
.noitnetta sih gnitcartta
ylthgil pil sih no tib yehS
ehtaerb ot eveirper fo tnemom a yehS gnivig ylerab
,swaj sih desaeler nomiS litnu
,detalumits gnieb kcid sih morf
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
kcab decnalg ylfeirb seye neerg nwo s’nomiS
avilas s’krahs eht htiw detaoc steg kcid sih erus gnikam
,buthtab eht ot meht fo htob eht del neht nomiS
,rehtegot selkna s’yehS fo htob desserp dna
.ti htaenrednu thgir ecaps egarots eht ni yehS rof sesirprus emos yawa gnikcut dna ecapskrow gnigassam sih pu gnittes
.sregnif sih htiw dnuos gnidduht a gnikam
,edis sih yb detarbiv enohp sih nehw
,sdnah sih htiw kcab s’yehS no cigam dekrow aneyh sseltrihs eht sa deb eht otni gniknis ylgnimees
ti dekil eh taht timda ot gnilliw ton
”.pu naelc uoy pleh em teL“
.ylkeem deilper yehS ".riS
,agniyaF yb ”stifeneb htiw ruessaM“ saw sihT
,ecap emas eht ta tpek nomiS
tnurg a htiw tekcaj s’nomiS yb gab sih gnippord
,tnemarepmet fo egnahc s’aneyh eht ta kcab sih hguorht nur redduhs a tlef yehS
roolf eht ot ti fo edis eno deppord nomiS
,wam s’yehS fo tuo dna ni sserp ylwols ot hguone lufdnim llits
.seninac sih htiw yltneg ti gnitib
,edam yehS sesion eht gninword
”?dnim ni evah ris seod tahW“
.spil s’krahs eht ot sinep sih fo pit eht desserp dna
nihc sih rednu thgir morf gnidnetxe
kcab depyt miS
.noitatpmet htiw dellif dna
”.wohyna ffo yad ruoy no ylrae pu ekaw ot deen oN .eituc ,pu tseR“
.kcab s’krahs eht gnidaenk ot gnitteg
,taorht s’yehS otni gnipmuh nageb eh sa ecaf s’yehS no gnikcams sllab sih
,sekorts sih htiw citarre gniworG
”stifeneb htiw ruessaM“   yojne esaelP
.od ot uoy rof gnihtemos tog I
yehS no kcid sih morf mucerp fo neehs thgils a gnidaerps
.ti fo esab eht gnihcuot nehw ylthgil reviuq ti gnikam dna
eno siht piks nac uoy
.kcid s'krahs eht revo yawflah ti gnidils erofeb no ti gninrut
.semit ta elbillug tib a eb ot yehS gniwonk
.selkna s’krahs eht fo og gnittel erofeb
,ylhguor os flesmih gnihctarcs morf yehS pots ot
.redluohs sih gnillor dna
,detser rebmem sih erehw sgel sih neewteb tils eht dna
”?nif ruo fo esuaceB“
,yletelpmoc tuo dellup nomiS
ria rof gniggeb ylgnimees
,htuom sih otni ecnartne kees eugnot s’aneyh eht tlef eh sa ylthgils htuom sih gninepo dna
.daeh sih gnikorts
ti gnizeeuqs ,redluohs sih no dnah sih desserp dna
.meht revo pirt eh tsel selkna s’krahs eht ffo stnap eht gniknay erofeb ton
erehw ecapskrow sih ot dnah eht yb krahs gnihsulb ylthgil eht del eh sa
,wam s’yehS otni htrof dna kcab spih sih gniyaws ylthgil detrats dna
.denedder gnieb llits ecaf sih etipsed gnilims
tsehc pu dehctarcs sih
,skcid rieht htob dnuora sdnah sih depparw dna
rebmem gnilgnad s’aneyh eht fo tnorf ni thgir denoitisop daeh sih htiw mih fo detnaw nomiS tahw dootsrednu gnivah
,deb eht ot txen doots dna
ti fo otohp kciuq a ekat ot ytinutroppo na nomiS gnivig
.hsif ,esolc ’nitteG“
.emosdnah ,trilf a uoy t'nerA"
,spih sih demriuqs yehS
,keehc s’yehS dekcil nomiS
.nihtiw neddih hteet prahs eht revo gnipiws eugnot sih
.gnimmuh sih rof evas teiuq
.niaga eltneg gninrut erofeb
.htuom sih ni deloop taht avilas eht deplug yehS litnu
elbat eht fo sedis eht ot smra s’yehS gnisserp ylsuoinomerecnu
”.dekaos er’uoY .ffo ti ekat ,nom’C“
.yehS ,taerg gniod er’uoY“
,kcab s’yehS no redrah nwod gnisserp detrats nomiS
ylivaeh gnitnap ysub oot
,ylteiuq delggig ylno nomiS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
loots a no gnittis yehS no detsisni nomiS
,sdrawrof daeh sih desserp dna denihw yehS
yrolg larutan rieht ot kcab enam dna liat sih gniffulf
,emit emas eht ta kcid s'nomiS pal ot tuo gnilggirw eugnot sih
,did eh sa yehS eporg ot ytinutroppo yreve gnisu
.no yal ot elbatrofmoc
,dnoces a tuo koot
,hcamots dna tsehc sih revo lla gnitrups dna
,edisni daol sih gnipmud dna
,dekool yehS draggah woh ta worbeye na desiar nomiS ”?yad hguoR“
,repeed eugnot sih desserp ylippah nomiS
,wam s’yehS fo tuo dna ni deppils kcid sih sa
,nwod kcab denael dna
aneyh ehT .hcuot mrif tey thgil s’miS morf mriuqs ot gnitnaw ton
ti gniwollaws dna kcid s’nomiS fo tuo dekael taht erp eht tuo gnixaoc ylregae
,yarg krad yb dewollof dna
emit siht gnitiaw tuohtiw ni kcid sih fo htgnel eritne eht gnihsup
,wam s’yehS otni
ylthgil sregnif sih desserp nomiS
,yleerf ni kcid sih hsup ot nomiS rof ylediw htuom sih denepo yehS
,krahs eht desiarp nomiS
,spil sih dekcil yehS ”…hA“
.desu eb ot ydaer tas elbat gnigassam eht
.spih s’yehS sdrawot gnisserp dna krahs eht rof pu meht gnitfil
,niaga deb eht dnuora degammur dna
,wollip kcen mrif a pu kcip ot ytinutroppo eht desu dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
gnisserp tsom sih dehsinif gnivaH
.selcsum eros teg ll’uoy dna enips ruoy no sserts sseltniop esuac tsuj uoY
.riS ,sdnah doog ni m'I esuaceb ylnO"
,yehS .rebmem s’nomiS
sa thgieh emas eht ni ti
.nwo s'miS tsniaga bur ot
.ay llet ot togrof ,hO“
dnah sih ni elzzon s’rewohs eht koot nomiS sa nwod tis krahs eht gnivah
.yehS teerg ot emac dna
,yehS dnuora delcric dna elbat eht rednu ti gniworht
tsiser t’ndluoc ohw
htuom s’yehS fo tuo dellup ylwols nomiS ,ylpeed gnilahxE
,ni sretemitnec wef a ni kcid sih gnisserp dna
,kcid s’nomiS ta deppal yehS
kcid sih gnitaoc avilas fo sgnirts kciht yb denioj
,tsehc dna kcen s’yehS revo lla sessik gnitnalp dna
,ylthgil daeh sih deddon yehS
,rehto eht pu gnikcip erofeb
nomiS retfa taorht sih fo ehca thgils eht etipseD
niaga ylsuoveihcsim dennirg nomiS
.s’yehS htiw dekcolretni
.yletanutrofnu ,sruoh fo elpuoc rehtona rof kcab eb t'now I
,stnap dna gel s’yehS revo gnidils sregnif sih
,ylper t’ndid yehS retfa ylthgil delkcuhc nomiS
,erofeb naht esnet ssel hcum gnileef kcab sih
,nwod mih gnisserp mra s’aneyh eht gnitsiser ton
,ffo mih yrd aneyh eht gnittel dna
eslup gnitarbiv lufrewop a tnes sinep sih dnuora gnir eht sa
yltnetni delims nomiS
,krahs eht kaos ot yarps eltneg a desu dna
.erom esohc tub gnir gnitarbiv eht desu evah ylpmis dluoc eh erehw
,lewot a gnibbarG
krahs eht revo dnah sih gnidils yllanoitnetni
.tuoba gninnur fo tol a os ,sremotsuc fo xulfni gib a tsuj ,haeY“
.ylsselpleh stniartser eht tsniaga xelf yehS gnihctaw yldesuma
.sdnah delliks sih fo hcuot eht yb deinapmocca
,gnitnap detrats renwo sti dna
.rethgil gnileef kcab sih
.egap AF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,stsurht s’nomiS fo hcae htiw wam sih fo srenroc eht morf loord yehS gnikam
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,hcuot delliks s’aneyh eht rednu denaorg yehS
yletelpmoc tuo gnillup
,ffo yletelpmoc ti ekat ot mih gniwolla ton epor eht ot eud meht tfel eh erehw
,ecap wols a htiw htuom s’yehS gnikcuf
,sgel s’yehS ot koot nomiS
yldesuma detrons nomiS ".emosdnah
selppin denot-niks sih fo eno elddiwt ot gnippots
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.reitsul nomiS gnikam ylno
wam s’yehS gnitcennoc muc dna avilas fo sgnirts kciht eht ta dennirg nomiS
.pot knat ytaews s’krahs eht ta gnikcip
s’yehS nwod sessik sseltnuoc htiw
pu gninael morf mih gnipeek dna tsehc s’yehS no dnah sih gnisserp
.swalc prahs sih morf skram gnihctarcs thgil gnivael
,deb eht tsniaga smra sih dezeeuqs dna
,noitapicitna ni spil sih dekcil dna
ylesolc yehS ,moor htab eht fo tuo tog dna delggig nomiS
.ynapmoc ti peek ot sinep s'nomiS rof deksa ti fi sa tsomla gnihctiwt
,seenk s’yehS ot nwod
,mriuqs dna enihw krahs eht gnikam
,epor eht pu detfil eh sa hsipmi denrut nirg nomiS
,nomiS fo sessik hsilkcit eht ta htaerb a ni dekcus yliratnulovni yehS
keehc s’yehS fo htmraw eht leef ot regnol tnemom a gniregnil
.enod saw eh emit eht yb der thgirb wolg
xal werg kcab s’yehS sa enut a gnimmuh
.egde eht revo mih gnihsup tuohtiw
”.xaler ot ti gnitteg troffe eht etiuq eb ll’ti ,spmarc ti ecnO
.sedis sih ta meht tes dna daeh sih rednu morf meht gniyrp yltnetsisrep tub yltneg
tub nomiS fo etsat rehtona gnitnaw
,ereht dna ereh stnioj sih gnivom seussi on sah yehS gnieeS
”.kcab eht ni yrotnevni gnivom tuoba gnilbmarcs tsuj ,tis ot tnemom a ton dah I erus edam snoitats eht nam yllautca ot elpoep fo kcal eht dna tahT
,neewteb deltsen rebmem diccalf sih dna sgel rednels sih gnilaever
,ffo krahs eht gnikrej detrats dna
.htuom sih ni deyats taht avilas htiw dexim muc eht deplug yehS
,ylmrif rehtegot selkna elap s’krahs eht gniyt dna
,ylsuoicoref delworg nomiS
.desuora sa yllauqe tub s'aneyh eht naht rellams ylthgils
,tsehc s’yehS no nwod thgiew lluf sih erob eh sa stnurg dna slworg s’aneyh eht sa llew sa
niks htooms s’yehS gnisopxe
hteet dettirg hguorht delworg nomiS
,no debmilc dna gniddon erofeb
,krahs eht dessik neht dna
.modnar ta tes s’tI
tsehc s’yehS fo pot no sdnah sih gnicalp
sepor yklis fo tes renniht
.gniraeh devol os eh scifironoh eht htiw nomiS gnisserdda yllanoitnetni ,delims yehS
htaerb trohs a ekat ot ecnahc eht koot yehS tuo dellup nomiS emit hcaE
,ylhsipeehs delims yehS
,ni rehtraf gnisserp erofeb
.ylideen dnah s’aneyh eht otni tsurht ot deirt yehS sa mih rednu xelf spih s’yehS gnileef
”!taerg 'niod er'uoY
,hcamots dna tils s’yehS revo kcid sih gnidnirg
,smra s’yehS fo dloh debbarg dna lavorppasid ni eugnot sih dekcilc miS
.sdnah s’aneyh eht fo eno gnidloh ,pal s’nomiS no
.drah os gnikrow rof mih drawer dluohs I spahreP
,nwod dna pu gnivaeh
yletaidemmi tsomlA
,ecnartne eht yb tekcaj sih gnidracsiD
,sdnah dna teef s’krahs eht gnidnibnu ot tog dna
,ecniw yehS edam dna
,htuom s’krahs eht gnirolpxe dna
hcuot tfos sih htiw peels ot krahs eht gnillul
.krahs eht morf ecnatsiser tuohtiw wam sih otni
daeh sih dial yehS litnu
.tuoba derac eh srehto gnicivres nehw tlef yehS erusaelp eht dna
ria gnineve eht fo tsug a hctac ot
.ot gniknis ylwols saw eh roputs eht morf kcab mih gnignirb ,yehS deksa miS
kwahom kcalb-neerg sih
ylsseltser dekcilf liat s’aneyh eht sa ecaf sih revo gnippird
.snoitca s’aneyh denam eht gnitsurt
.hcamots s’yehS fo mottob eht dehcaer eh sa
,gnineve teiuq eht ot nwo sih no nomiS gnivael
,rebmem ytfeh s’aneyh eht htiw dellif gnieb htuom sih fo noitasnes eht gnivol
yldliw gnihctiwt kcid nwo sih
,emyhr eht gnipsarg ylkciuQ
htaehs sti fo tuo gnigreme ylwols kcid nwo sih
,ni kcab gnikcams erofeb kcab rehtruf spih sih gnillup detrats nomiS
naelc kcid nwo sih gnipiw erofeb edam ev’yeht ssem eht morf ecaf s’yehS naelc gnipleh
deb eht ni pag eht hguorht roolf eht ot poord liat sih gnittel
.seye sih eno gnirevoc dna edis eht ot gnipoord
repeed tib a eciov sih ,detseggus nomiS
,eerf enam neerg dna kcalb ,dliw sih tel aneyh eht
kcid s’yehS dnuora dnah derevoc-mucerp sih gnipparw ,derrum eh
.deviecer eh txet eht gnikcehc ,pu ti kcip ot gnirehtob tuohtiw neercs eht ta deppat dna ylthgil delims miS
.edisa lewot eht gnicalp dna
nwo sih ekil hcum sliat htiw esoht rof tnaem
.keew siht emit driht eht s’tI ?niagA“
tsehc s’yehS no gnisserp
nif kcab s’krahs eht ot yaw rieht gnikam sdnah sih
,agniyaF yb ”stifeneb htiw
,taorht sih otni dna wam s’yehS tsap gnihsup
rood eht ni nrut yek a draeh miS ,retal elihw gnol a toN
,ylwols spil sih dekcil dna flesmih denethgiarts nomiS
,degreme htgnel lluf sti litnu tuo ti gnixaoc
.ffirdim eht fo retnec eht ta thgir gnippots ,hcamots
erusaelp htiw redduhs yehS ekam ot htgnerts thgir eht tsuj borht s’ti
yehS fo gninihw tfos eht gniyojne
.ssakcaj taht rof revoc ot etal krow ot evah I os tuo deppiks rekrowoC .citceH"
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.tniop s’nomiS evorp ot gnivres ylno
ylthgil delahxe miS .tsehc sih ot
”.hsif ,no dloh retteB
,noitcafsitas htiw gninnirG
,pord yreve gniwollaws ylregae krahs eht
.smra sih htob gniruces
,emoh sih no nwod gniraeb regnol on nus gnineve s'remmus eht htiw sseltrihs yats ot gnitpo
.dniheb gniwollof
dnoces elgnis a rof aneyh eht gnippots ton redduhs eht
gnicalp ,sdrawkcab
.tib a rof gnitnap
,yltneg daeh s’krahs eht gnikorts ot tog dna derrup nomiS
ylthgils dehsulb
,ecnartne eht hguorht derebmul krahs ehT
noitalucric eht ffo tuc t’now epor eht os pag hguone tsuj htiw
”?meht esufer reven uoy tcaf eht gnisuba tsuj t’nera yeht erus uoY
,yltnatcepxe redduhs mih gnikam dna
.ekorts yreve htiw taorht s’yehS otni gnihcaer
.spil s’yehS no muc nwo sih fo etsat eht gnidnim ton
spirts neerg yb demarf ruf kcalb sih
.mih revo aneyh emosdnah eht no gnisucof seye sih
dnoces fo elpuoc yreve dehctiwt ydob s’krahs eht elihw
,smra sih htiw tsehc s’yehS no nwod erob aneyh ehT
hcamots desopxe sih ot gnippiks dna
eht deb eht fo pot no kcab debmilc nomiS
,niaga yehS gnirusaelp detrats dnah esohw nomiS gnicnivnoc ,hguone doog tub
.gninworf etipsed elkcuhc aneyh eht edam taht noisserpxe derit a fo ijome na yb ylesolc dewollof ,deilper yehS ".yletanutrofnu
,gniporg erom htiw ttub sih decarg aneyh eht tsel revo deppilf ylkciuq yehS
”?huh ,yldab muc ot gnitnaw yob ydeen ,dooG .hooO“
.pu gnimraw emit rieht koot yeht retfa
.swalc s’nomiS yb dekram
,kcid s'yehS revo dnah sih gnidils yllanoitnetni
,wam s’yehS edisni flesmih gniniard retfa
,ecalp ni sgel sih detfihs yliratnulovni dna
sesion gniggag thgil htiw ni dexim
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.etamilcca ot krahs eht gniwolla
esirprus ni psag ot ylno pu dleh eh htaerb eht delahxe yehS ”!..hA“
”.emit uoy fo tib a evresed dna yletal drah gnikrow neeb ev’uoY
,stsurht sih htiw rehguor gniworg dna pu gnideeps
,detpurretni ezoons thgil sih htiw yliraelb gniknilb
,hcamots sih revo gnirevoh sinep s'krahs eht
,htaerb sih xif ot yehS rof detiaw yltneitap nomiS
ylthgil detcennoc selcsum owt erehw kcab s’yehS no tops a ta regnif delian neerg dna yarg a deddorp aneyh ehT
”.tey enod t’nia I ,kcab ruoy nO“
,oga gnol degnarra nomiS eciffo dna moordeb dnoces eht sdrawot gnidirts
.llew sa deb eht ot deruces meht gnidnif
,sdrow s’yehS etufer t’ndid aneyh ehT ”.oot taht ,haeY“
,muc mih gnipleh rof nomiS knaht ot tegrof t’ndid yehS ,ylivaeh gniffuh
nwod yaw sih gnikam erofeb
”.yehS ,ti devresed dna taerg enod ev’uoY“
,ylleb dna tsehc denot sih gnisopxe
,mih tsniaga gnibbur ruf tfos s’aneyh eht gnileef
,kcid sih dnuora detcartnoc gnir eht sa htaerb a ni kcus yehS gnihctaw
,ffo stnap sih koot dna deb eht no nwod tas eh sa
,eciov delffum a htiw denihw dna
,ylluferac erom eht lla kcab ruoy fo erac ekat ot evah uoy snaem ti tuB“
,tnemom a rof htiw delddif eh hcihw regnif sih dnuora dekooh gnir a htiw gninethgiarts
,ylthgil pmur s’yehS dettap nomiS
,gniog uoy peek ot hguone tsuJ"
.boj eht rof erow netfo eh skcals dna pu-nottub eht naht elbatrofmoc erom gnihtemos otni egnahc ot gnitnaw
deb eht ffo tog nomiS
.deit ylsuolucitem nomiS stniartser eht tsniaga gniggut regnol on dna
,pil sih no tib krahs eht sa reivaeh gniworg htaerb s'yehS yb deinapmocca
,no gnir eht denrut dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,nwod dial eh sa ylthgil detnurg krahs ehT
.mraw ylbatrofmoc ti gnikam
,muc sih wollaws ot krahs eht gnicrof dna taorht s’yehS ni peed degdol kcid sih
.tib a rof uoy taert emmeL .erem’C“
,wam s’yehS otni kcab kcid sih dehsup eh sa
”.taht tuoba yrroS .eb thgiM“
,tnemesuma s’nomiS ot hcum denialpmoc yehS ”…wO“
ruf deuh maerc fo tfut kciht a yb derevoc yltrap
nruter ni yehS gnitsat
.mih evig t’ndluow parts gnitarbiv eht esaeler rof dna
ruessaM“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
.erofeb naht ynapmoc s'nomiS ni elbatrofmoc erom
,tsehc s’yehS otni swalc sih gud nomiS
,eveirper tuohtiw ti dekcuf ylsuoinomerecnu
dnah rehto sih htiw
deb eht no gnixaler ,delahxe yehS
.mih ot tnatropmi os ton saw raewrednu gniwohs
spil s’yehS gnissim yllanoitnetni
ylthgil deffuh yehS
.trofmoc s’yehS rof ereht morf trats ot gnitpo
,ylthgil dehgis dna
ot yehS rof gninoitom ,deb eht dettap dna yehS del nomiS
nomiS fo dnuos gnihtoos eht ot ffo gnizod detrats krahs eht dna
,esnet tsom saw kcab s’yehS tlef eh erehw
,deb eht dnuora deklaw eh sa gel s’yehS ta dezeeuqs nomiS
ylmrif nwod smlap sih htob desserp nomiS
,keehc s’krahs eht desserac dna yehS revo denael nomiS
srae s’aneyh eht ot elbiduani tsomla saw aelp teiuq s’krahs ehT
.aneyh eht ta ecnalg ot pu daeh sih detfil dna deticxe gniworg
,ylbatrofmoc erom nwod yal ot
stnap s’yehS gninottubnu
,ssik rieht ekorb nomiS retal htaerb A
,rebmem yhtrig s’nomiS etsat ot gnitnaw
trihs sih denottubnu nomiS
,ffo cirbaf niht eht deggurhs dna dehgis yehS
yliddig eugnot sih fo noitom eht decart seye s’yehS sa gnihctaw
.emas eht lla yawa mih evag noisserpxe gnihsulb
yldekoorc gnilims aneyh eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dnoces a rof s’yehS gnivael ton seye sih
esirprus ni peem krahs eht gnikam
.sevresed ti noitnetta eht ti evig dna
,tsirw eerf s’yehS ot epor eht fo edis rehto eht deit dna
daeh sih rednu smra sih dedlof dna
krad denrut eliforp s’yehS dna
,ni sretemitnec fo elpuoc tsal eht desserp eh sa krahs eht mlehwrevo ot gnitnaw ton
"?krow s'woh ,yeH"   agniyaF yb
.yaw rehto yna ti dah ev’dluow eh taht ton
ecalp ni ylthgils detfihs yehS
.pleh s’yehS htiw muc sih morf naelc hcamots dna tsehc s’yehS gnibburcs
retal tnemom a ylduol gninaom krahs eht
,erusaelp htiw lworg yllanoisacco mih gnikam bus sih fo htuom tew dna mraw eht
,thgiew s’aneyh eht htaeneb gninihw dna ylthgils gniggag
,mih fo llems eht
,wam s’yehS otni yaw eht lla desserp dna
nwod denael nomiS
,neercs sih ta gnikeeP
”?I nac ,oot mih gnihsaw tuohtiw krahs a egassam tsuj t’naC“
,ssecorp eht ni keehc sih gnisserac dna
,yawa mriuqs t’nac eh os krahs eht gniruces fo ”nrecnoc“
,kcab ruoy ni selcsum lufrewop dna etacirtni evah uoY !ogniB“
,regnol tib a rof ecap wols sih ta tpek nomiS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
wam s’yehS edisni yldliw gnihctiwt kcid sih
.ti fo thgis eht ta ylthgils denediw seye esohw krahs eht ot gnikniw
,pu deps eh elihw mih rednu mriuqs dna enihw yehS gnikam
.lamron naht regnol rof taorht s’yehS edisni deltsen kcid sih tpek nomiS revenehw
”.ot dnetta ot retteb gnihtemos evah I kniht I ,rettam on tuB
.era uoy yob regae ,doog a tahw ,nraD"
nwod elttes ot flesmih decrof krahs eht litnu redrah etib dna lworg nomiS ekam ot gnivres ylno
,moor eht fo renroc eht ot ffo seohs sih gnikcik elihw moordeb eht ot delriwt dna egdirf eht morf ados a flesmih debbarg dna
,elkcuhc a htiw tuo detniop yehS
,nwod kcab denael dna derrup miS
ssik eht no gnisucof
,ffo debmilc dna sdnah sih yb demrof epahs eht ekorb nomiS ".era
.spil sih fo srenroc eht gnitfil elims dnik a htiw ti no teg
.pleh dluow ti ekil gnileef
,pu tog dna ylhsipmi delims miS
,stsirw s’yehS fo eno dnuora ti deit dna
,nwod dehcaer dna
,ylthgil htrof dna kcab spih sih deyaws dna elcric esool a gnikam
,boj sih ot kcab tog dna enohp sih desolc krahs eht sa
ti htaenrednu epor eht gnippils
”…ssssssssseY“ .eldruh taht hsup gnipleh avilas eht
”.yob doog a s’tahT“ ”.ris ,ydaeR“
,hsipeehs sih hguoht
,seye sih esolc ot esohc ohw ,taorht
,daetsni kcid s’yehS ta gnippal dna
ylthgil tsehc s’krahs eht dessik miS
,afos eht no ti werht dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.noihsuc a sa tca ot
,ylthgil ti gnihcnip erofeb
reffo tnelis taht pu gnikat yldalg aneyh eht
,sdrawrof desserp ylthgil aneyh eht litnu
,tils s’yehS no rebmem gnibborht sih desserp dna
ecaf sih ot yaw eht lla tohs yehS taht muc eht pu gnippal
”.yehS ,em gnildnah llew yllaer enod ev’uoy ,nmaD“
”.miS ,pu em leef ot emit erom detnaw tsuj uoy ekil tlef ti em oT“
.elims thgil a htiw dekniw eh dna
.tnemeticxe s’yehS etipsed ylbatrofmoc deltsen
flesmih rof tnemom a yehS gnivig ton
.htuom sih fo tuo dna ni gnidils kcid eht gnikcus no gnisucof dna
pu daeh sih porp ot kcen s’yehS rednu ti gnidils
tib a pu ti gniydit
,resolc egde yehS gnileeF
.dnah s’nomiS revo mucerp fo tib a gnitrups
ffo ti nrut ot gnirehtob tuohtiw ffo gnir gnitarbiv eht gnidils ,no dial krahs
,trap tsom eht rof nuf rof setirw ohw
deb eht rednu gnikaens dnah eerf sih
,ylteiuq delbmum yehS ”…esaelp ,riS“
yltneg krahs eht ta gniggut
,s’yehS htiw spil sih dekcol dna
.htuom sih ni gniregnil muc s’nomiS fo etsat hcir tey ytlas ylthgils eht
.spil sih detfil taht elims a nwod dloh ot elbanu tub gnitniuqs
.dab os ti gnitnaw etipsed esaeler rof geb dna enihw ot tnatculer
raewrednu eht htiw gnola ffo meht gniknay dna
,lworg peed a htiw repeed neve gnitsurht retal htaerb a
emac ylkciuq ylper A
daeh s’krahs eht no dnah sih gnitser
epor eht fo egde esool llits
,reilrae dehcnip eh elppin eht ot nwod yaw sih gnikrow
”.hguoht ,uoy no rebmun a did llits I ekil smeeS“
yletanoitceffa keehc s’yehS gnikorts dna kcab enam sih gnikcils
,sinep sih dnuora depparw gnir eht yb eveirper tuohtiw desaet gnieb kcid nwo sih fo tsul eht yb nevird yltrap
noitom ralucric a ni kcab s’krahs eht dedaenk dna
yehS fo pot no gnibmilc ,derrum aneyh ehT
,s'yehS tsniaga kcid sih sserp ot sdnah sih gnisu saw aneyh eht elihw naom dna lacov eb ton ot gniyrt
.erutcurts s’nif ruoy fo esuaceb nosrep egareva eht naht os erom hcum
.nwod gniyal nehw neve taht ekil selcsum ruoy dloh uoy fi xaler t’nac uoY“
”.robal gniod emit drah a dah reven uoy yhw s’tahT
spil s’yehS neewteb gnihsup sinep sih fo pit eht
,demriuqs dna denaorg yehS
,tsehc deoottat eht ot dna
.srenoissimmoc rof yllanoisacco dna
ecaf s’yehS gnikam
ti gnirongi ta troffe tseb sih etipsed
s’yehS edisni yaw sih gnigde
aneyh eht fo pit eht ta pal ot eugnot sih gnisu dna
.niks desopxe s’krahs eht revo lla eralf spmubesoog gnikam