.deit sbmil dna nekorb senob gninigami
.reverof nwot llams a ni deppart gnieb
.gid dna levohs ym barg I oS
,uohsneguuY yb uoy rof daer
,uohsneguuY yb daeR
gnirebmemer ton fo era
efil ot selkcarc retnuoc regieG ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tbuod gnilior dna snoisserpmi
yawa dekcol serusaert
roloc gnissim elpmet A
.enots derettahs dna ssalg nekorb
psil a dah I emit eht
.gnirebmemer-ton fo yromem a
eht eb eroc nomed eht evael I
stnemom yrassecennU
.luos ym fo sretaw eht rof
eci eht tsap rettilg ees I tub
”!taht tegrof reve dluow eno oN
;delkcitnu liat s’nogard gnipeels
rorroh etirw ot tnaw I   .neetriht
nevele xis evif
knab eht ot esuoh eht gnisol tuoba etirw ot tnaw t’nod I tub yas staerg eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
ronoh fo ecalp a ton si siht
relles-tseb a etirw ot epahs on ni dna
.la te Æ yb meop a
,”yromeM“   yojne esaelP
,doohdlihc ylrae rieht srebmemer eno oN
,tsael ta rO   .yad yniar a rof
tsulrednaw fo flow
ruof ta ,em saw taht os draeh I
.noitidepxe siht fo esoprup eritne eht gnitaefed
rehtaf reh fo diarfa lrig A
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
,.la te Æ yb ”yromeM“ saw sihT
niart eht no skcatta cinap gnihtrib
egelloc otni gnitteg ton
dlrow eht dne nac taht
.ereh detaromemmoc sdeed taerg on
monev fo esimorp-flah raey 000,02 a sedaced rof gniretsef
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.seloh fo lluf si yromeM
nepo ti pop ot levohs eht fo tsiwt kciuq A
eulb fo hsalf tnaillirb a esaeler
.tsulrednaw fo flow
redderhs eht ot dettimmoc
serehps-flah eht neewteb enil a s’erehT
.taoc hcnert a ni snogard lareves fo desopmoc teop a ,.la te Æ yb
.snel nredom a hguorht deterpretni
erusaert a htiw eno spahrep
,relevart wollef ruoy floWcaM boR si sihT
,sraef doohdlihc tuoba etirW
.yad yniar a rof yawa dekcol
sepahs sroloc ylno tub
ecafrus eht sehceerb llehs muillyreb ehT
edalb ym stlah tsorfamrep latneM
.rebmemer dluow I ,em ot deneppah taht fi ,yleruS“
nihtiw muinotulp eht fo esimorp
daetsni meht tuoba etirw nac I
seramthgin ni derebmemer eb ot sdrow
rof sdrow on dah ehs sgniht gniod
sniamer wodahs ym ylno litnu gninrub
tseilrae yM .emussa I
.neewollaH rof regnaR rewoP knip eht gnieb