”.sisemeN ,klat dna tuo emoc llew sa thgim uoY
.noitanod elbatirahc a yb dehctam em llik ot gniyrt tneps rallod yrevE .drow ruoy tpek uoY“
,em ot dnecsednoc uoy tel I ,raey yrevE“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.smraws ni selissim taps smroftalp hcnual naenarretbuS
evaw tsrif eht diova ot devrews dna evod eH
.secalp ni dehsurc saw niatnuom eht fo tuo gnisir lluks muinatit nautnagrag ehT
”sisemeN rosseforP ,samtsirhC yrreM“   yojne esaelP
,yobdooG ydduB yb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
”.yeknom uoy ,uoy htiw si lerrauq yM
nac uoY .daD regdaB yldduC eht
uoy knahT :daer eb ot
,ediserif eht ta niaga uoy ees ot epoh ew tub
.ycneuqerf cificeps a ot desucof dna deworran neht
.nepo denway lluks eht fo htuom ehT
”.desimorp uoY .em esongaid ot noisiv orcim ruoy gnisu oN“
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
”.deregnadne stneconni on dnA
.sraey ytfif rof em tsniaga evitceffe neeb t’nevah esohT“
.gniraeh-repus sih tuo denword raor ehT
.rehtegot tnelis erew yehT
.rial niatnuom ’sisemeN rosseforP drawot deeps cinosbus ta yks eht hguorht dedilg xepA
.rosseforp eht ot kcab atad gnilennut tbuod on
.sisemeN rosseforP drawot dnah a tuo dehcaer xepA
”sisemeN rosseforP ,samtsirhC yrreM“
,”yobdooG ydduB yb
yobdooG ydduB yb
em tel dluow uoy hsiw I“
,seye sih morf tnerrot a ni dewolf sevaw citengamortcele dna ,detniuqs xepA
.yllanif dias sisemeN ”,uoy llik lliw I“
.yawa dnah s’xepA deppals sisemeN
.gnikool tuohtiw ti koot sisemeN ,emit sihT
.worbeye na dehcra dna ti drawot pu denrut xepA
,sredaer fo pihswollef ruo fo lla
.revo delbuod dna hguoc gnikcarw ,tew a evag eH
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
.tneconni eht regnadne dluow I fi sA“
.dehguoc eh ”,ot desu ti ekil hcterts t’nseod tegdub s’tsitneics dam A“
,yrots rehtona rof
.niaga dnah sih dereffo xepA  ”.redlo teg I dna
,flesym fo flaheb no dna
.neerg ylkcis a pu til eye enO
.eertkniL sih no detsil dnif nac uoy tra dna ,seirots ,aidem laicos esohw ,mih/eh
.rood tnorf ’sisemeN rosseforP ta nwod dehcuot xepA
.detrats eh “—gnisu oN“
.srehcnual nwo rieht otni kcab demmals dna langis s’xepA wollof ot dereev selissim eht ,hguone eruS
aremac eht fo tifeneb eht rof dias eh ”?selissiM“
.xepA teem ot tuo delffuhs fitom lluks neerg a ni detaroced sehtolc bal dezisrevo yldab ni tsitneics gniyerg ,neknurhs A.nepo
”.hguone od uoy tel I“  “—
.lla retfa ,yadiloh a no swodniw yna elttar ot deen oN
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ikahK
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
,regnorts teg uoy dna
”sisemeN rosseforP ,samtsirhC yrreM“ saw sihT
,syadiloH yppaH .raey wen eht ni
.tbuod on ,sresal eht yb dediuG
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,raey tsacdaorb 3202 ruo sedulcnoc sihT
.mih otno dekcart sllihtoof eht morf sresal derarfni ,dnim sih dessorc thguoht eht sA
sledom eseht no suidar nrut a doog oot ton—
seirots rieht detubirtnoc evah ohw sretirw esoht lla dna
.mih wollof ot dnuora cra meht ees ot ylno—
.deretaw seye ’sisemeN
”.sisemeN rosseforP ,samtsirhC yrreM“