tsol t'nevah yeht tuB
warning me things aren't working right.
some horribly tragic way.
No, I don't, you're not out.
I say quietly.
.shtaerb kciuq neewteb dap I
Rough day.
breaking into the apartment and
Megan was out.
556,13:70:00 >-- 594,92:70:00
.em pleh ot yrt t'nseod eh lufknaht m'I
be a new story for you next time.
gnikcats ylreporp no krow ll'eW
He pauses for a moment to
.USI ,sthguoht sih rehtag
rof eltsirb selkcah yM
I nod.
In response, Donovan tilts his
.ylluf erom ssik nac eh os daeh
Donovan stands up and let's go with
.ffo trihs sih gniggut erofeb llab ym
.srettam esle gnihtoN
539,84:20:00 >-- 575,54:20:00
It takes both of them to hold the cup
tub ,erehwyreve retaw eht gnillips tuohtiw
.serised netfo os eh sa esolc sa eB
.yojne esaelP
back when he kisses my forehead.
557,24:20:00 >-- 531,14:20:00
saw ohw floW detniap suoiragerg ,hU
519,35:60:00 >-- 487,15:60:00
.doog ynA
566,75:50:00 >-- 541,55:50:00
.on a tuo elbmurg I dna kcab dlof srae yM
.yrroS
560,54:20:00 >-- 526,34:20:00
,yaw eht lla rood eht sehsup navonoD
.su fo rehtien od ot gniog t'niA
reven ,swolf dna sbbe deen yM
He'd reached the prime of his life
elihw ylrae oot raf ti tfel dna gnuoy
?citohcyspitna ruoy esaercni uoy diD
attention without breaking the moment.
I'm at khaki doggy on
.margelet dna rettiwT
.uoy morf raeh ot evol d'I dnA
Our precious beyond any price.
586,61:40:00 >-- 504,41:40:00
.dlrow eht ni esle enoyna naht eroM
.enim si eh dna sih ma I
.emoh ta kcuts uoy gnipeeK
tension in my shoulders.
.kcab evig ot erom evah dluohs eW
ees nac seye detsujda thgin yM
.tnemom a rof em ta skool eH
I squeezed my eyes shut
.ti erongi ot yrt dna
Aye.
.erofeb deciton evah I
.sknahT
.yako uoY
Connor.
over my own feet, but the
569,63:01:00 >-- 591,53:01:00
595,55:80:00 >-- 507,35:80:00
Usually I sniff.
,renroc eht ni tab llabesab a s'erehT
My tail wags slowly and his puffs up.
down the inside of my arm,
his shoulder, but my ears flicked
.yhcaep tsuJ
.em rof od uoy lla etaicerppa od I dnA
teg erad eh sa esolc sA
.tceffe elttil oT
And I can't bear to be touched.
The room feels like it's
.htrof dna kcab gnippit
As I work, my body backs
.yteixna eht morf nwod
denrael evah tsum yehT
the short, soft fare back and
.kcoc ym tuo gniward ylwols htrof
I reach out to rubbish cheek.
wounds that had only begun to heal.
538,13:01:00 >-- 527,03:01:00
576,62:60:00 >-- 598,22:60:00
576,02:90:00 >-- 510,71:90:00
And now you do.
ym fo kcab eht seldarc eH
.haeY
557,75:10:00 >-- 584,45:10:00
.gninetsil rof uoy knahT
Fighting back guilt.
Content warning.
likely kiss his lips.
.ekil atoyiK
I hope.
I notice Paul, and then
.eye eht ni mih kool
.leef yb krow dna seye ym esolc I
kcab eht elihw kcen sih swonk I
While he continued his administration's.
a sa enohp sesu eh ,kcab semoc eh nehW
worst was the lack of emotions.
.yrc I
And I feel small and
.esuap siht ni elbarenluv
575,15:30:00 >-- 531,05:30:00
501,70:00:00 >-- 513,40:00:00
587,93:31:00 >-- 520,73:31:00
.retaw fo puc a em teg ot moor
tsol si srexob  sih fo roloc ehT
Yeah.
414,73:80:00 >-- 575,63:80:00
So many times we need to meet
.gnitnaw ,tfel eb dna yawflah
covers on do all fours.
597,11:80:00 >-- 510,11:80:00
.ezigolopa ot deen t'nod uoY
592,91:10:00 >-- 569,51:10:00
.delzzuP
567,65:30:00 >-- 551,45:30:00
but I know how to fight mean.
School was fine.
.ma I lla esuaceB
evitcartta tsom eht t'nsi eH
.god fo eciov eht oT
.ekiL
,traeh ym morf ,tsuj eW
He asked softly.
,na ekam ll'I ,haeY ,yas I neht ,lleW
It doesn't take long before
tuo nworg a teg ot deganam I
584,45:10:00 >-- 577,25:10:00
pill, would you take it?
I say shakily, as he pulls
.ygolopa derepsihw a htiw kcab
I suppose not.
There are mentions of past
.samuart tsap dna mrah-fles
m'I esuaceb egnirc I dnA
.yltfos oot enon ,sesruc eH
598,64:21:00 >-- 518,24:21:00
hold myself close to his chest.
540,14:11:00 >-- 573,83:11:00
sink back into the bed.
Not particularly.
My ears fall back slightly.
.repsihw nac I yllanif dnA
.god fo eciov eht ot gninetsil er'uoY
.taht detcepxe I tuB
raeh I sa kcilf s'ayaM
The ball, my shoulder moves to my side and
.rof ,ym hguorht emoc sregnif tfos s'ti
a gnidael m'I ,yadoT :DOQ ikahK
mood, but it does feel nice.
Until the bed creaks has
.srevoc eht rednu spils navonoD
504,41:40:00 >-- 557,21:40:00
Pressure in my cock bills until the
.sneppah gnihton tub ,sehca tsomla pit
.ot deen t'nod uoY
I
.sgel ym neewteb wolg mraw ehT
My attention wanders.
si esolc em sdloh eh sA
.uoy evol I
.ronnoC ,uoy evol I
.DOK yb thgindim si yrots s'yadot dnA
595,91:21:00 >-- 545,51:21:00
for feeling for tense muscles.
529,04:01:00 >-- 529,73:01:00
.ysmulc era sregnif yM
545,93:10:00 >-- 575,63:10:00
brushing across the thin scars.
I leaned my head harder
.ffins dna kcen sih otni
.Y
You're not getting rid of either
.selkcuhc uoy ylkciuq taht su fo
,tuo thgin a uoy gniviG
.mih no regnil seye yM
396,73:00:00 >-- 321,43:00:00
.stnap sih devomer eh sa elims I
Everything had closed in.
Heavy sunk makes me flinch, but
railimaf yvaeh eht raeh I neht
I got to learn how to cope sometime.
.no yekil atoyiK yb thgindim saw sihT
Give me a minute.
528,02:40:00 >-- 596,81:40:00
fo edisni strap gnizeeuqs si gnihtemoS
You could have, let me know.
595,61:11:00 >-- 500,51:11:00
512,93:21:00 >-- 568,73:21:00
.elims I dna enim no regnil spil siH
erom eno rof sehca llits em fo traP
596,81:40:00 >-- 528,71:40:00
.drapoel wons a fo sllaftoof
an office than lack of exercise.
.detcepxe I naht ekawa erom tol a er'uoY
.roop  sih debbarg I
don't say that he sniffs you're
.nac uoy sa drah sa gnithgif
Therapy sucked.
ruoy ykcoc yb uoy rof daeR
If you insist, I mumble.
In the windows to our souls, there
.laever nac evol ruo ylno shtped era
The bedroom door opened
.ni skaeb nahpinoD sa ylwols
.ykcoc m'I
I whispered earnestly.
He whispers.
Then an unsteady pile of
.roolf eht ot srettalc erawrevlis
Our now.
else to do, but lie here.
can look him in the eye.
dna em ot txen deb eht no stis eh nehT
567,83:80:00 >-- 573,83:80:00
.snoitseuq diputs ksa ot ton denrael s'eH
517,04:90:00 >-- 504,83:90:00
.esiwrehtO
573,71:41:00 >-- 526,31:41:00
my sheath and his fingers brushed
.ylhsipeehs yas I
sih gnibbur enod m'I emit eht yB
563,00:10:00 >-- 563,75:00:00
gnol a rof em ta skool eH
My voice stammers.
.taht etaicerppa I
the reflected gleam from my eyes.
He never pushes me too far, keeping me
.erusaelp tnatsid fo ezah eltneg a ni
?sruoy ekat uoy diD
pours to grasp the prophet cup.
578,63:90:00 >-- 547,43:90:00
be a good fit, please get in touch.
.sdem fo gnikaepS
.thgin lla tlef I
I croak.
517,01:80:00 >-- 509,90:80:00
559,91:31:00 >-- 529,61:31:00
until my breaths matches.
After spending the evening alone.
sih no sllor eh degaruocnE
.llitS
He reaches a poor out to brush my muzzle.
.eyB
.mih ta redluohs ym revo kool I
.flesruoy fo erac ekat ot tog uoY
.mih rof hguone sI
.srepsihw eH
.lohocla fo eton prahs ,tniaf a s'erehT
He asks quietly.
.luuJ ym sbur yltneg eH
then it starts looking for weapons.
.emit eht lla ytliug leef I
.ot desoppus erew uoy ekiL
tuc ot em dael dluoc taht ssenitpmE
.hcuot siht tpecca nac I
You spend every other
.em htiw keew eht fo yad
?uoy llet I nac tahW
It's Paul leaves my cock to
.ecarbme sih otni em llup
521,30:01:00 >-- 583,10:01:00
570,05:70:00 >-- 555,74:70:00
kitchen, the light fades out.
505,85:80:00 >-- 568,55:80:00
558,11:20:00 >-- 573,80:20:00
spent dealing with my issues.
.enim fo emirp eht retne ot tey evah I
555,35:30:00 >-- 541,25:30:00
Oh, who says.
.sevink eht yb yrroS
593,15:40:00 >-- 506,84:40:00
.niaga gnikrow strats niarb
my fingers through his thick
my head while his poor strokes, my back.
440,83:80:00 >-- 414,73:80:00
.mih ta pu kool I
.hgih oot si stsoc oN
.thginoT
.syas navonoD
of yellow seeps under the bedroom door.
.enot ym denetfos dna ylwols tuo ehtaerb I
593,12:11:00 >-- 500,81:11:00
And you can find more of his stories
.eloC tod DOK ,etisbew sih no
.emoclew er'uoY
ym gnileef m'I dna tib a pu sraeT
etartnecnoc ot evah I oS
535,70:01:00 >-- 569,30:01:00
.nruter nI
I do.
share love in the same way.
I close my eyes and breathe out slowly.
There was no happier, sad, only
.ssenitpme elbaraebnu knalb a
.thgindiM
,ekawa saw I fi ekiL
.noinapmoc ediserif ,lufhtiaf er'uoY
.eson ym sllif tnecs sih dnA
507,53:10:00 >-- 577,43:10:00
547,34:80:00 >-- 450,04:80:00
The pain in my chest eases
ym sa kcab dlof srae ym dna
587,51:80:00 >-- 541,31:80:00
565,85:11:00 >-- 565,55:11:00
So David and I did in the MDR session.
.kcab sih deen I saw mih fo
583,43:01:00 >-- 546,23:01:00
580,82:70:00 >-- 567,62:70:00
.kcab puc eht dnah I sa repsihw I
.oN
He kisses my forehead.
507,74:40:00 >-- 562,64:40:00
561,41:30:00 >-- 551,21:30:00
I do.
project year one by for planet.
There's days with Megan, right?
.eye ym morf raet a depiw eH
590,24:21:00 >-- 535,04:21:00
derised eb ot deen thgim sleef hcuot siH
but I can't get them out.
.rae ym otni srepsihw eH
Yeah.
Donovan gets up with a stiff
eht fo tuo sklaw dna naorg
Meds kicking in.
.em ot txeN
.elttil a skriuq eh nehT
586,13:30:00 >-- 515,72:30:00
.teem seye ruO