seires ydoB gnignahC eht etorw ohw
,stnerap reh ot deneppah dah tahw rebmemer t'ndluoc ehS
.nedrag eht tuoba gnivom ,pu tilps yehT
.sesserd hguorht detros ehs erehw ebordraw reh ot yawa deltsub dna doots eilleN
,mU" .roolf eht ta derats dna nwod reh rednu der fo edahs ytterp a dehsulb eilleN
.alraC ta detniop dna desolc ebor reh dellup eilleN ".nwod
.pil reh no redrah nwod gnitib
.nosnaH ssiM ,em eiraeD"
.seert eht fo ytefas eht otni kcab evid dna etalp eht barg thgim ehs ,kciuq saw ehs fI
.no peels ot deb a ,yad yreve deF
.edis eht morf emac eciov s'ydaL hsilgnE ehT "?truh uoy erA"
.sserd thgin eulb a htiw revo emac eilleN ".esle
.tuoba kniht nac I lla er'uoY
"...seitud ,snoitagilbo evah I tub ,alraC ,uoy evol I"
#    .tiaw ot ni delttes dna llab rethgit a otni flesreh dellup alraC
,derepsihw ehS ",ffo siht teg em pleH"
,yldneirf dna nepo saw noisserpxe reH
.naf repap a htiw flesreh ta gninnaf
.enobralloc reh ot nwod devom alraC sa denaom dna derevihs eilleN
,niaga kcab dna ,spets owt ,nips ,spets owt
,rorrim eht nI
,tuhs degnab etag nedoow A
,reh ssik otni denael alraC sA
.taht htiw uoy denedrub evah t'ndluohs I .ma I ,oN"
.liat s'alraC fo esab eht dekorts dna
.denaom dna dehcra eilleN litnu elppin reh no dekcus ehs sa bun s'eilleN revo regnif a debbur ehS
.lwoy a htiw eert eht fo tuo liat revo daeh gnilbmut alraC gnidnes ,drawrof dehctip dna niaga dekcarc hcnarb ehT
.noitcerid s'eilleN ni liat derruf-kcalb dna ,mottob dednuor ,spih ediw reh tnualf ot sesucxe gnidnif
.noisses gnikamevol teews ylralucitrap a retfa rehtegot deldduc yal yeht sa deksa alraC
,sgel derehtaef s'eilleN ssorca liat reh bur ot deunitnoc alraC hguohtla
.htuom reh otni denaom alraC dna denethgit pirg s'eilleN
deistruc alraC ".alraC m'I
.gnikool t'nsaw ehs thguoht ehs nehw alraC ta revo gnicnalg tpek ehS .ti ot nward tey
,dirbyh-naws a dna dirbyh-tac kcalb a
.ecnef nedoow llat a ni dedne yella eht fo dne rehto ehT
a gninrom txen ehT
,drawrof tperc alraC
.evael ot elbanu ,detsuahxe ,gnivrats reh tfel dah ytilaer eht tuB
.dekool ehs naht retsaf saw repeekesuoh dlo eht tub ,gniliar eht rof detrad alraC "!redurtnI"
.smra reh otni reh dellup eilleN "...hhhS"
,pag eht ni deraeppa ecaf s'eilleN
.reh tsniaga gnixaler
.nosrep eno rof hcum oot ,doof hcum oS
,oitap eht tsap dehsalf alraC sa gninediw seye ,senocs reh morf pu dekool ydaL hsilgnE ehT
.egairram ni dnah ym mih dereffo rehtaf ym dna
".thgin tsal rof gnikool erew nem esoht yttik eht eb tsum uoY"
,resolc tperc dna spil reh dekcil alraC
.stfig sa ,reh ot meht evag I"
.trohs eilleN gnittuc ,delttar rood kcab
.talf ylsuoiruc saw hcihw
,esoog a delgnarts enoemos ekil sdnuos llac riehT
.sgge eht no detaxif seye ,smra reh gnipmup ,revoc morf tsrub ehS !woN
.regnif reh rof revo koot htuom reh litnu ,gnibbur yltneg llits
.ebor a rof ebordraw reh ot dekan deklaw ehS
.wodiw a ,rehtaf ym sa dlo sa s'eH"
.dne s'yella eht gnikcolb dekrap nogaw yddaP eht sdrawot yawa deluah dna detsuor erew sdirbyh lamina-namuh suoirav eht sa ekaw rieht ni dniheb tfel erew selbmurg dna ,skeirhs ,slworG
.hguone thgir uoy tif dluohs siht kniht I ,ereH"
.spets eht nwod deirrac dna hsid a otno sgge depoocs ydaL ehT ".sgge
,pu yawflah tuoba tilps knurt ehT
.sselkcer eb tonnac I .seitud ym era yehT"
.eilleN dna alraC ekow rood tnorf eht no gnignab
,rehto hcae no snrut gnikat ,gnildnof dna gnissik ,deb eht ni rehtegot yal yehT "!eroM !alraC ,hO"
.sserd nrot reh ffo dellup ylkciuq dna kcab elims tub pleh t'ndluoc alraC
,tsrif ta detatiseh eilleN
"-yad yreve rehto hcae ees nac ew nehT
".siht yojne ll'uoy esimorp I ;eltneg eb ll'I"
.smelborP" .selppin tcere ,kcalb rieht htiw stsaerb dednuor reh ot llef ,alraC ta decnalg seye reh dna deplug eilleN ",ylnamoW
"ssarB dna kliM" saw sihT
,dellac yeht ",yttik-yttik ,ereH"
"?em pleh ot tnaw uoy od yhW"
.detsixe nwonk neve t'ndah alraC taht srood denepo dah sserd detfig ycnaf s'eilleN
.tuhs rood eht dekcilc eilleN sa yawa deltsub ehs tub
si yrots s'yadot dna
.reh ot pu sesserd dleh eilleN sa deilper alraC ",dirbyh-tac kcalb a m'I"
.erif renni htiw thgila seye ,pu til ecaf s'eilleN ".saciremA ehT"
.ssendekan reh revo ebor a werht eilleN elihw mra s'repeekesuoh eht ta gnikcik detsiwt alraC
.liat dna srae s'alraC ot dekcilf seye s'eilleN ".letsap
?erahs dluow ehs spahreP
.pets hcae neewteb dehcnurc sevael
,yenom ym gnivas neeb ev'I
,stnargav gnipeels fo enil eht nwod gnivom erew seibboB demrofinu eulB
.mirb eht ot ti dellif sllib hsilgnE fo skcatS
s'eilleN .flesreh noitanicsaf niatrec a timda ot dah alraC
.esruc ot detnaw alraC dna rood eht no dednuos kconk A
s'eilleN decalnu ehs sa mottob s'eilleN otni stib etavirp reh gnidnirg
.tuoba kniht dluoc ehs lla saw ti tey
,deklaw ehs sa dehctiwt liat reH .deppart saw ehs
.epacse t'nac I etaf ehT"
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
.esion yna rof trela ,deleviws srae-tac detniop reH
# ?nosregoR .rM saw ohW .gnidnuop traeh
.nedrag eht gnihcraes seye ,doots ydaL ehT "?yttiK"
.sreusrup reh esol ot ecalp tcefrep eht
.stnetnoc sti revo denrub ytisoiruc ekil-tac s'alraC
"?noos os evael uoy tsuM"
.elbat dne eht no pmal lio eht no denrut dna
.ytnelp si ereht ,yrgnuh llits era uoy fi dnA
,nodnoL fo steerts eht no dirbyh-tac a sa pu gniworg tuobA
.knurt kciht a htiw eert modnar a pu bmilc ot sehsub dna seert eht hguorht detrad alraC
.rood eht ta derutseg eilleN "!hhS"
.wonk t'ndid ehs aera nA
.ssol fo egniwt a delfits alraC dna yawa dellup eilleN "?nosnaH ssiM"
.txen gnimoc saw tahw gniwonk ,degnirc alraC
fo eno gniraew s'ehS .ralgrub tac a ,feiht gnimoolb a s'ehS"
.gniwolb seltsihw
.spil reh ssorca regnif a gnidloh
.nwog eht fo gnical kcab eht ta gut ot flesreh dnuora gnihcaer
.erom od nac I spahreP"
.nehw rebmemer t'ndluoc ehs ecnis emit tsrif eht rof lluf yldesselb
.edisni ees dluoc alraC os ti delgna dna nepo pot eht dekcilc eilleN "?ereht ni s'tahW"
"?yttik thgirla uoy erA"
.eb ot ton saw ti tub ,dah reve d'ehs xes tseb eht neeb dah sihT
.secal eht htiw gnilbmuf
.reh ekow thgin taht nwod deb ot nesohc dah alraC hcihw ni yella eht nwod rehtraf noitommoc A
,yad fo thgil hsrah eht ni laer mees t'ndid
# ".eno elbaromem a ti ekam s'tel nehT"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,stixe on dah moor llams ehT
.ytisoiruc htiw gnihctiwt liat dna gnileviws srae tac
.ereht tnemnosirpmi tsal reh morf evila depacse ylerab tsuj ylno d'ehS .esuoh-krow ehT
.llaw eht dehcaer nem eht sa nedrag eht fo dne eht ta noitommoc a saw erehT
.sserd s'eilleN ta dekcohs ,deppots dna ,gninepo eht fo tuo deppils alraC
.taeb a ssim t'ndid eilleN ".stfig
.yrd saw ecaf reh tub ,sdnah reh ni feihcrekdnah a detsiwt ehs dna seye s'eilleN ni delkraps sraeT
.hcrop eht no enola ydaL eht gnivael
sregnif reh neewteb tsaerb reh
,mosob s'eilleN fo sdnuom tnecselapo
.sraet htiw gninetsilg seye ,denworf eilleN ,dehsinif ehs nehW
.drah gnihtaerb ,alraC morf yawa dellup eilleN
.alraC ot dnah devolg etihw a tuo dehcaer
.edis reh dnuora delruc liat
,gnitnap tsomla dna der saw eilleN
.sserd reh otni gnippils erofeb keehc eht no ssik kciuq a eilleN evag ehS
.kcab og t'ndluow ehs ,oN
.sserd s'eilleN no liat reh gnikorts
.nedrag etavirp egral a otni gnippord ,revo dellor dna pu flesreh dellup ehS
.snoissessop regaem wef reh gninodnaba
.resolc reh dellup dna sredluohs s'eilleN dnuora smra reh tup alraC
.nepo dekaerc rood eht dna depparcs rab ehT ?eilleN
sa thgilsag eht ni wolg ot demees tsomla srehtaef s'eilleN yaw eht gnirimda ,sdnah reh no daeh reh tup alraC
.lufrednow dednuos tI
.deciton yldrah alraC tub
.uoy hcuot ton tub ,uoy eeS"
.gab eht ta daeh reh debbob alraC ".tsehc ruoy edih oT"
.sessik nelots ,tuoba gnikaenS .siht
,stoob yvaeh rieht ni depmolc yehT .ybboB a toN
wodniw nepo eht edisni saw dna ti delacs alraC dna esuoh eht fo llaw kcab eht derevoc ecittal derevoc-yvi na
,reh ta seye reh dettab alraC dna der rethgirb dehsulf eilleN
.gninrom txen eht alraC ekow setalp fo rettalc eht dna sdrib gniprihC
sessert yklis esoht hguorht sregnif reh nur ot detnaw alraC
.erahs ot hguone naht eroM
.ti revo depard gnihtolc s'nem erom dah hcihw ,mra na tuo dleh ehS ".oot
.em ksa uoy fi sdrib elbirroH"
.revoc on htiw ssarg tuc fo esnapxe egral a ssorc ot evah d'ehs etalp eht ot teg oT
,kcab s'eilleN delddarts dna pu dehsup alraC ".ffo
"?nodnoL tfel reven ev'I wonk uoy diD
.niaga llef ecaf reH
".uoy rof tuo dekcip lla esuoh-krow eht ni ecalp a tog ev'eW
.sserd reh derehtag ehs sa rorroh ni derepsihw ehS "!tpelsrevo I"
.dnah s'eilleN koot ehs ,niaga doots ehs retfA
.erus m'I ,erehwesle hcraes rieht denrut evaH" "-nem esoht tuB"
.revocdeb delbmur eht ta gnihctulc
.spil reh morf delbmut sdrow eht sa neve flesreh gnitah
.noitanibmoc gnikirts a erew srehtaef etihw dna riah kcalb ynihs
,eilleN dniheb dehcaer alraC
.hcamots reh ni noitasnes thgit a reh evag thguoht ehT
.deusne elffucs trohs a dna spetstooF "!won evaeL"
...I .ereh ma I enoyna llet t'nod esaelp tub ,seY"
".pleh ot od dluoc I gnihtemos saw ereht hsiw I
.gnicaf eb dluoc eilleN ekil ydaL hcir a etaf elbirroh tahw gnirednow ,deddon alraC
.seert eht dna reh neewteb llaw a saw ereht ,yletanutrofnU
,rood eht decaf dna deppots alraC
,senotselbboc eht nwod dednuop teef erab s'alraC
.rood s'eilleN ni deraeppa tius reppad a ni nam dega-elddim a
.nwod mlac ,enoyrevE"
.delialf dna dekeirhs repeekesuoh ehT
gnol a htiw alraC decnelis dna pu tas eilleN
.riah s'eilleN hguorht dnah reh nar alraC ".sselkcer
,ytidun s'alraC ta dessarrabme saw eilleN
;eno ysae na saw pu bmilc ehT
dellor eilleN elihW
.ecaf reh no denetsilg sraet yawa dellup ehs nehW .ssik
,tsehc dna kcen reh fo niks desopxe eht no yllihc saw ria nwad-erp ehT
.repeekesuoh eht ot flesreh ecnuonna t'nseod dnA ?nwad erofeb stisiv ohW ?dneirf A"
,rehtegot ,yawa nuR"
,gniticxe dna ,wen gnihtemos saw sihT
.ruf dna niks reh gnilffur srehtaef eht gniyojne
,ekops ehs sa reh ta revo kool t'ndid eilleN ".evol
".rehtegot thgin tsal ruo eb lliw sihT"
seirtsap fo rettalp gnimaets a htiw edistuo emac nwog s'tnavres a gniraew namow redlo nA
,neeb dah pu gnimoc naht redrah saw ynoclab eht morf nwod gnibmilC ".yrt
.ereht ecnef ruoy revo deppoh ehs dna ,yttik ruo tsol eW" "!tuo teG
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
.derepsihw eilleN "?alraC"
.reh rof gnirevoc er'uoY"
.sesserd eht revo reh ta ecaf a edam eilleN ".nawS"
.llaw eht fo sedis rehto eht no tuoba evom ot deunitnoc nem eht tub
.sraet reh neewteb elims a tuo tel dna reh morf htolc eht koot eilleN ".yrros m'I"
",ylreporp uoy knaht ot tnaw I"
.delley eciov elamef A "!uoy ,yeH"
.draob a sa ffits
.nus eht was ehs sa denediw seye s'alraC
,tuo deltsub diam ehT
.hteet reh dehsurb kcen s'eilleN no srehtaef regnol ehT
.yrots ruoy em llet dna senocs dna aet evaH"
dniheb ybboB eht gnicap tuo ylisae
ti teg ot tnaw t'ndid ehs dna nur eht no gnieb morf yhtlif saw niks reH
.evol alraC ,t'nac I"
# ".seibboB eht rof rennur a dnes I elihw yrtnap eht ni feiht siht kcol ,doowroN .srM
.gab enotsdalG egral a deirrac ehs dna
.gnitros ot kcab tnew dna dnuos gnimmuh a edam ehs "...srae
.repeekesuoh laciretsyh eht dna ,sserd nrot reh ni alraC ,ebor eht ni spag eht hguorht gniwohs niks ,eilleN ni koot eh sa denediw seye siH "?no gniog s'tahW"
.yrtnap nehctik eht fo senifnoc llams eht ni elba saw ehs sa hcum sa decap alraC
.ydaL gnuoy eht ot txen ti tes dna
,deb retsop-ruof evissam eht rednu delggirw dna teprac eht ssorca delwarc alraC
.delriwt dna dennirg ehS ".esiugsid A"
.me-ta dna pU" .bulc sih fo dne eht htiw reh ot detniop dna seye gnimaelg reh deciton dah ybboB gnihcaorppa nA ".dirbyh-tac ,uoY"
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.stifeneb rieht dah sexelfer ekil-tac
.eilleN fo potrevo delwarc ehs sa dekcoc srae reh dna dehctiwt liat s'alraC fo dne ehT ".meht
.steehs eht ni rehtegot delgnat ;dekan yal yehT
.dneirf a si ehs ;redurtni na t'nsi ehS"
.ezad a ni yad eht fo tsom tuoba tnew ehS
.sdnah reh fo skcab eht derevoc taht srehtaef etihw tfos tub ,lla ta sevolg eb ot ton tuo denrut sevolg ehT
.gniltsur striks ,dehgis eilleN
htaerb a welb alraC sa
,sdrow s'repeekesuoh eht ni lavorppasid saw
,noisiv thgin ,sexelfer ekil stiart lacitcarp erom htiw enog dah rekam reh ,yldaS
.striks deniats dna nrot reh ni
.desopsidni m'I taht nosregoR .rM llet esaelP"
.kcab reh pu gnitloj smsaps gnilgnit eht rednu dehtirw alraC
,reh retfa revo pu gnibmilc naht rehtaR
.dnuorg eht ot wol flesreh gnipeek
.htuom reh fo foor eht gninrub dna sregnif reh gnidlacs
.sparcs rof gnithgif
.srehtaef s'eilleN fo tnetxe suolevram ,lluf eht neddih dah sserd ehT
ekil no gniog peek t'nac I"
"?ekilsid uoy nam a yrram ot sselkcer erom ton ti sI"
eilleN ,esool erew sgnirts tesroc eht ecnO .delggig eilleN .tesroc
.lworg-tsomla yksuh ,wol a ni dias alraC
.suoicanet erew seibboB eht tub
?thgin ta moor sih otni og uoy ees nehT
.ecnalab reh pleh ot liat a dna ,gniraeh-tac
.seidob s'rehto hcae gniyojne tneps yeht thgin eht fo tser eht dna ,sessik neewteb ni rennid derahs yehT
.hcni na fo noitcarf a dexaler alraC ".dneirf
#   .ssentfos rieht ni gnithgiled
,xob draobdrac reh morf detlob alraC
.rehtegot meht detiawa taht serutnevda eht dna dlrow eht dnuora pirt rieht tuoba deklat yeht sa tnemeticxe htiw gnimmirb
.spil reh teem ot pu htuom reh gnignirb
tah relwob ediw a rednu neddih erew skcol gnol reH
.deklat eilleN sa ecaf reh ta debbad dna htolc eht koot yltneg alraC
,llaw eht tsniaga pu desserp tops efas reh morf gnivom ton ,deksa alraC
.reh htiw eilleN gnillup ,edis eht ot dellor alraC ".lliw I ,hO"
.enigne maets krowkcolc wen rieht ffo dewohs dna tseW dliW eht morf erew yehT
.teerts eht nwod gnihsad
.yawa gnillup dna kcab reh gnihcra ,erusaelp ni depsag alraC
.doof suoiciled eht fo setib neewteb ni elat reh eilleN dlot alraC ".pleh
.tas alraC sa dnah reh dezeeuqs eilleN ".esuohkrow
"?nosregoR .rM s'ohW"
,esuohkrow eht ro modeerF
,srehtaef nwod llamS
.sgel reh gnissorc ,deb eht no pu tas alraC ".lufrednow
.derepsihw alraC "?gniraew uoy era tahW"
,dennirg htob tuB
.smra s'eilleN morf depard taht srehtaef eht ta gnilevram
.slirtson reh tih tnecs railimaf A
.lufrednow s'ti erus m'I"
.thgis fo tuo erehwemos etag a nepo gnikcik ,ni delcric yeht
.tsaef eht espmilg ot gniyrt ,hcnarb gib a no tuo delwarc dna deffins alraC
"!gniticxe os dednuos tI
".ylf uoy pleh nac I"
.ssa dna stsaerb reh ot noitnetta ralucitrap gniyap
.striks deniats reh fo tuo deppirts alraC .ytrid
,sregnif reh morf rettub dekcil alraC ".eilleN
,hguone eb dluow slliks gnikcip kcol regaem reh taht epoh tsniaga gnipoh ,rood eht deirt ydaerla d'ehS
.raew rof esrow on ,pu tas alraC
.hcnul erofeb esuohkrow eht ta kcab eb d'ehs dna ,seibboB eht llac dluow rehtaf s'eilleN
.edistuo eht morf derrab saw ti tub
,laem derahs rehtona retfa ,gninrom eht nI
,dnah eno htiw htuom reh ni sgge deffuts dna eert a fo knurt eht dniheb dekcud alraC ,sehsub eht fo ytefas eht ni kcaB
.etal oot saw ti tub ,ezorf alraC
.gninepo dehsinif woleb rood eht erofeb
,noisnam s'eilleN ot kcab flesreh klaw ot demees teef reh gnineve tahT
.letsap era sesserd ym llA
dah rehtaf ym hsiw I .naem er'yeht sulp
,rewol dessik ehs ,nehT
.pu gnikool tuohtiw detniop ehS ".ereht thgir era htolchsaw dna nisab retaw
.nwod etihw enif eht gniton
".ytterp era srehtaef etihw eht kniht I"
.elppin tcere s'eilleN tsniaga tuo
.shguot dna seillub sa sutats rieht ni tnedifnoc
.pleh nac I spahreP
"?nosnaH ssiM ,esle gnihtynA"
".ereh seitud ev'I"
".tisiv s'nosregoR .rM erofeb egnahc ot moor ym ot gniog m'I"
.eilleN sdrawot deyahsas alraC edun a ,naelc dna htooms dehsaw niks tunrettuB
.ecaf reh nwod gnimaerts sraet ,pil reh tib eilleN
.sdworc eht otni dnelb nac I ,esiugsid a htiw ,naelC
.llef sraet eht woN
.sgge evah I .yttik-yttik ,ereH"
.steerts eht ffo teg ,boj a dnif neve spahreP
.ffo meht teg ot em dniheb teg tsum uoY"
.meht htiw ylf t'nac I"
,ecaf reh evas ot emit ni pu sdnah reh tog d'ehS
.enola neeb syawla d'ehs taht tsuj
,daeha erehwemos deltsur seerT
,ffo ti dellup dna pu tas
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
".tuo teg ll'ew reh dnif ew sa nooS
.srae detniop s'alraC fo eno tep ot pu gnihcaer ,dehgis eilleN ".wonk t'nod I"
.rood eht fo edis rehto eht morf dias repeekesuoh eht
.opxE taerG eht ta snaciremA emos tem I"
.ecaf s'eilleN ssorca ti dekorts dna pu liat reh dekcilf alraC "-I fi tahW
,detnap eilleN ",yrros m'I"
,dnuora kcab eb lliw nem esoht enigami I
.yppahnu uoy ekam lliw taht seituD"
.nwod gniwols neve tuohtiw etalp eht pu gnipoocs
.egadnab fo htgnel a htiw reh dniheb pu emac eilleN trihs eht pu dekcip alraC sA
.alraC ,lufwa s'tahT"
.yrt ll'I" .detatiseh alraC
.denepo rood eht sa ezeens a kcab thgif ot dah alraC dna ytsud saw deb eht htaenrednU
.deb eht no tuo ti dial dna ebor eulb eht koot ylluferac alraC ".hguone
.oot ,uoy rof ereh eno evah I"
.tas ehs sa dekaerc alraC evoba deb ehT
.thgilf reh ot tser eht detrela seirc s'ybboB gnuoy eht ,revewoH
.suoregnad kool t'ndid ydaL eht dna ,doog os dekool doof ehT
.sbulc yllib rieht htiw sekirts ro skcik suoiciv htiw meht gnikaw
.yrots dnoces eht no wodniw a ot detniop eilleN ".em
,yttiK" .noitcerid s'alraC ni kool ot seotpit no doots neht ,nedrag eht ni htap eht no ti tes ehS
.skooB goD wobniaR yb dehsilbup keeW krahS detide dna
.yawa dellup eilleN sa deirc alraC ",pots t'noD"
,rehtegot yellag regnessap eht ot knalpgnag eht pu deklaw yeht sa riap ddo na edam yehT
.kcen s'eilleN dekcil dna delims alraC ".ma ydaerla I"
"?nosregoR .rM yrram ot t'nerew uoy fi ,od uoy dluow tahW"
"?yrgnuh uoy era
.tnew ehs sa eerf-raet dna naelc nwog s'eilleN peek ot gniyrt saw alraC esuaceb yltsom
.eilleN ,ydaerla os enod ev'uoY"
.liat reh fo esab eht degassam eilleN sa sgel s'alraC dnuora delgnat striks s'eilleN
.saciremA eht ot ecivres pihsria citnaltA-snarT wen eht no egassap dekoob nemeltneg fo riap a thgin tahT
.yffulf dna tfos saw htolchsaw eht tub ,looc saw retaw ehT
.ylsuoiruf flesreh gninnaf saw ehs dna ,dehsulf erew kcen dna ecaf reH
".uoy pleh ot tnaw I"
.drawrof dekrep srae reh dna pal reh ni delruc liat kcalb reH
ehT ".sruoy epacse uoy pleh ot tnaw I tub ,etaf ym epacse ot elba eb ton yam I"
.eciov reh ni terger saw ereht tub
.mra erab s'alraC no doolb fo liart a ta detniop ydaL eht ",tuc era uoY"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,reh rednu demsaps dna naom tfos a tuo tel eilleN
.ebor hsulp a no dellup ehs
.ezeerb eht no reh ot detfaw sgge deirf dna tsaot fo amora gnizilatnat ehT
.srehtaef s'eilleN ta deppal eugnot tfos reH
.sevael eht hguorht tuo gnireep
.sraet dehsnu htiw gninetsilg sehsal ,pil reh tib eilleN
.em rof ereht tiaw dna moor ym ot pu bmilC
.pot no eilleN htiw deb eht otno kcab rehtegot llef yehT
.noitpmusnoc fo raey tsal deid efiw siH
;yarg llud a retaw eht dna emirg htiw kcalb saw lewot maerc eht ,dehsinif ehs emit eht yB
.elims suoitcefni s'eilleN ot flesreh fo erom gnisol ,eilleN detisiv ehs thgin hcaE
,noitcifnaF yb dehsilbup
.yrc ot nageb alraC ".tuoba
.gnihsarht liat dna daeh reh fo pot eht ot gninettalf srae ,ezorf alraC
,ylwols flesreh dehsaw alraC
.desaet alraC "?lla ta saedi oN"
.dlrow eht ees ot detnaw syawla I"
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.dnuorg eht morf elbisiv reh evael t'ndid taht ni pu lruc ot reh rof wolloh tcefrep a gnivael
.yawyna ,rettam t'ndid tI
.hguorht deltsub ereh gninrom tsrif reh despmilg dah alraC taht repeekesuoh eht dna ,denepo rood s'eilleN
.reh detsurt alraC dna erecnis neeb dah eilleN
.uoy rof reppus evah I ?nosnaH ssiM"
.dedaf thgil eht litnu
.nedrag eht ni gnitiaw saw eilleN erehw
.smlap reh delkcit srehtaef s'eilleN
,nihc s'eilleN deppuc dna drawrof devom alraC
,yawa teef wef a tsuj doots ydaL ehT
.pu teg ot emiT" .rood s'eilleN morf dias repeekesuoh eht ",eilleN ssiM"
.pot eht revo sregnif reh gnikooh ,depmuj dna ti ta dehsur alraC
.rood eht dniheb alraC deoohs ehs dna ,ediw werg seye s'eilleN
.uoy ees ot ereh si nosregoR .rM ?nosnaH ssiM"
"-pihs remaets a no egassap rof hguone evah I teb I
.hcrop eht ot alraC del dna delims eilleN
.gnihtemos ro nibor a ekil
.tnemom eht rovas ot detnaw alraC dna
,ni pu delruc d'ehs xob draobdrac eht morf tuo dereep ehS
.niaga desolc dna denepo rood kcab eht dna deknalc sehsiD ".ssiM ,aedi dooG"
".evorppa reven dluow nosregoR .rM dna rehtaf tuB"
.drah reh dessik neht ,tsaerb reh no ti decalp dna dnah s'eilleN debbarg ehS
.sevael dna trid eht gnoma suourgnocni gnikool sreppils dna nwog thgirb
.ecal eht no srehtaef s'eilleN fo yna hctac ot ton luferac ,sserd eht fo tuo reh depleh alraC erofeb
.yawyna dnah reh koot alraC
.won od ew ekil klat toN
.eilleN ot swen eht ekorb alraC
,tieced fo ecart yna rof ecaf s'ydaL eht dehcraes alraC ".erahs
.rewsna eht gniwonk ydaerla ,yawa dekool alraC ".erehwyreve rO
.deppid hcnarb reh dna kcarc a saw erehT
.ekawa detrons ehs litnu eilleN koohs yltneg alraC
.su fo owt eht tsuj ,thginot
,oitap eht ot pu kcab tnew ydaL hsilgnE eht retfA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,tiusrup ni erew erom owt
.evah dluow ehs ,rrup dluoc ehs fI
.seye desolc-flah rednu morf eilleN dehctaw ehs ,niks reh ffo emirg debburcs alraC sA
,tius s'nam gnuoy a erow ehS
.yawrood nepo eht otni gnivom
.ekaw t'ndid tub ,derrits eilleN reh ot txeN
.ytisoiruc htiw gnikrep srae
.eilleN ,uoy teem ot desaelP"
.meht htiw siht ekil neeb reven dah ti tub
.ti ni eilleN dedulcni efil rehtien
.rood eht nepo gnikcarc ,dias repeekesuoh ehT ".uoy
.reh ssik ot pu denael dna alraC ta pu delims ehS
.pil rewol reh gnitib ,yawa daeh reh denrut eilleN
,depsag alraC "!sgniw evah uoY"
"!mih ekil neve t'nod I"
.enoyna htiw snoitaler lauxes dah reven ev'I ...I ,alraC"
"?mih evol t'nod uoY"
.rood eht yb yart eht evaeL" .yrram dluow
"?uoy era tahw ,ksa nac I fi ,mU"
.deb eht rednu morf tuo delggirw alraC .delffins eilleN ".egairram
.ekil d'uoy fi uoy rof taht naelc nac I"
,ynoclab eht ot yaw reh edam ehs sA ".pu
.erehwyna og nac ew ,em htiw emoC
.nees eb t'nac uoy ,kciuQ"
".tem tsuj ylno ev'eW"
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dnA
.doof hguone ton ,sruoh gnileurg ,sdeb yhtliF
".tseW dliW eht ot pirt ruo ecnanif oT .yrwod yM" .dennirg eilleN
...srae eht tub ,liat ruoy edih lliw triks ehT"
.nedrag etavirp a si sihT"
.doowroN .srM ,flesym ot gniklat tsuJ"
,nodnoL fo steerts krad eht hguorht evow dna dekcud alraC
",tnemom a ni ti eveirter ll'I
".enut a yrrac ot elba eb d'I neht tsael tA
".uoy knaht ,yrgnuh llits ma I" .pleh ot regae
.pleh rof gnimaercs ,no gnuh dna sserd s'alraC fo kcab eht debbarg ehS
".slraep ruoy dna ,oga shtnom wef a gnissim tnew taht sesserd dlo ruoy
.evael t'ndluow ti ,ereht saw ti taht won tuB
.morf emoc dah aedi neddus siht erehw erusnu ,revo denael alraC "!og s'teL"
"?uoy seticxe gnihtoN"
.esuohkrow eht ot kcab og t'nac I" .deredduhs alraC "...I
depsarg dna pu dnah a dehcaer eilleN
.esuoh s'dnabsuh ym ni boj a uoy teg ll'I yrram I retfA"
.tlob ot ydaer ,desnet alraC
".em naht regnuoy raey a naht ssel si tsedlo eht ,nerdlihc eerht sah eH
,ecaf reh depiw alraC ".t'nac I ,oN
,s'alraC tsniaga spil reh gnivom ,dednopser eilleN
.niks reh tsniaga retaw ekil gnidils ,dekool yeht naht neve retfos erew yehT
,srevoc eht rednu rehtegot denoops yeht ,derit werg yeht nehW
eilleN htiw thgin dna yad reH
.smra reh fo tuo gniworg srehtaef etihw eb ot tuo denrut ecal saw thguoht s'alraC tahW
.txen eht dna lacigam saw niaga thgin tahT
deb fo tuo dils ehs sa dellac eilleN
,pir egavas a htiw gniraet sserd eht fo kcab eht ,eerf dellup alraC sA
.alraC ta deralg nesnaH .rM ".repeekesuoh
.dias alraC ",elbuort ni eb ll'uoy ,ereh em sdnif repeekesuoh ruoy fI .og tsum I"
.enim naht rekrad hcum os si gniroloc ruoy tub ,em sa ezis emas eht tuoba er'uoy gniht dooG"
.stius gnihctam gnittif-lli gniraew
.elbat eht no sregnif ynwod reh demmurd eilleN ".uoy rof gnitnuh
,tsehc dna spih reh no thgit dna sgel eht ni gnol oot
,dneirf s'rehtaf ym si eH
,tsap eht ni nem htiw dial d'ehS
.dnuos tsethgils eht ta gninekaw
eilleN dna steerts eht ot kcab og dluow alraC worromoT
.gnippird ti dnuof dna setavirp s'eilleN ta bur ot nwod dehcaer alraC
.seot reh ni gniggid ,hcuorc sretnirps a otni pu devom alraC
erehT ".mih llet ll'I ,thgirlA" .derepsihw ehS ".smelborP"
,tuo dna pu sbmil reh dednetxe alraC ,smra reh gninaelc nehW
.detsetorp doowroN .srM "!ssiM ,tuB"
,eilleN ,ydaL ehT ".eilleN m'I"
.tfelc reh ot nwod ylleb dna stsaerb reh derevoc ,ecaf s'eilleN no esoht ekil
"?tsrif htab a spahreP"
.striks fo eltsur a saw erehT ".doowroN
llams eht ssorca srae yrruf dna ,eson ,skeehc reh debbur alraC
.deticxe os neeb d'ehs ,esuohkrow eht ot reh tnes ,reh dnuof seibboB eht emit tsrif ehT
,repeels thgil a neeb dah syawla ehS .rebmuls thgil reh morf alraC desuor rood eht ta kconk tfos A
.esaerg fo pord yreve fo ti dekcil alraC ytpme saw etalp eht nehW
"ssarB dna kliM" yojne esaelP
.tuo yaw yna ees t'ndluoc alraC tub
,dribgnos a dekcip
"?thginot ,kcab emoC"
.nwot fo trap recin a otni dna skcod eht morf yawa reh desahc d'yeht ,ti wenk ehs erofeB
.nepo dna tuo flesreh gnidaerps ,deb eht no kcab yal dna dehsulb eilleN ".hsiw I"
.srehtaef tfos reh tep dna
;pohs ycnaf a ta krow dnuof alraC yad eht gniruD
.deilper lrig eht ",uoy knaht ,oN"
,tuhs seye reh dezeeuqs eilleN "?uoy lliw tuB"
.desolc sserd nrot reh llup ot tseb reh did dna denethgiarts alraC
".sserd naelc a uoy teg s'teL
",sniap ruoy pleh ot ,daerb dna puoS
.edistuo selit eht ssorca delffucs spetstoof thgiL
.pael htooms eno htiw ti revo gnitluav ,ecnef eht dehcaorppa ehs sa depmuj ehS .reh
.daeh sti koohs noitcelfer s'eilleN
ttub s'alraC dnuora sdnah reh depparw eilleN sa ecaf s'alraC delkcit srehtaef nwod tfoS
.der dehsulf ehS ".gnissarrabme tib a s'ti ,lleW"
,renroc eht dednuor ehs emit eht yB
.esle hcum ton dna ,ytterP"
ten.relleknosidam no
,enog ydaerla saw ehs doow eht otni dehsarc ybboB eht erofeB
.dehctiwt liat s'alraC
".ereh tuo seciov draeh I thguohT
.truh t'ndluoc setib wef A
riah kcalb gnol s'alraC
.tah a dna sserd gninrom ycal wolley dna etihw a gniraew ,ega reh dnuora ,ydaL hsilgnE gnuoy a was ehs ,daetsnI
,relleK nosidaM naI yb "ssarB dna kliM"
.dnah s'alraC koot dna deplug eilleN ".steerts
.tsafkaerb reh gnitae nedrag eht gnikoolrevo oitap a no tas ehS