.esuoh s’xof rellat eht ot yaw rieht no deunitnoc yeht
”.esaelp ,eeffoc-c ..hU“
”?worromot uoy eeS
.retnuoc eht dniheb morf meht gnihctaw llits saw ssertiaw ehT
,renid eht morf epacse ysmulc a edam riap eht
.maerc deppihw gniggas fo
,woble sih morf wap s’dneirf sih dekoohnu dna ylwols denrut sexof eht fo rellat ehT
.knip fo edahs gnihctam a dehsulb srae rieht fo hcae fo sedisni eht sa
.sraet denethgirf htiw pu gnillew dna ediw seye
”.snoops fo elpuoc a dna
.denetfos erutsop dna sredluohs sih ni ssenesnet eht dna
sexof eht fo rellat eht
.ekil d’eh tahw xof rehto eht gniksa yldetniop rehtar erofeb redro eht nwod gnikat ylpmis
.sehtolc ”ecin“ fo lausac tsom rieht dna
tros emos dettimmoc d’yeht rehtehw ot sa erusnu ,suovren
,ekahsklim derahs eht morf ssendloc gnidaerps eht retfa egnahc emoclew a ria gnineve mraw eht
,ssenkrad ni flah dna thgil ni flah
”…togrof I sseug I
.reilrae dias I tahw kcab ekat I“
,gnihtyna naht pissog erom
.daeh detlit htiw dneirf sih dehctaw rellams eht elihw
,yknal sa ffo emac eh
,ts1 enuJ  tuo semoc
,evael ot euc rieht sa taht gnikaT
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”sexoF dna sekahskliM“ saw sihT
”sexoF dna sekahskliM“
.rab a otni deklaw sexof owT
eht dekcip etaciled xof regral eht
- hsifiaw erom demees xof retrohs eht eht saerehw
.rehto hcae morf ssorca nwod deppolp dna
,thgin ecin a llits saw tI“
,rehtona htiw tem elzzum sih nehw esirprus ni gnitnurg
”?owt uoy ,eb ti
.elbat eht yb ylduol mug reh gnippop setaks rellor no tac a yb detpurretni saw
.erom ecno ffo deliart eh
,rab eht ta stis ohw sgod dnuoh dlo
,bruc eht otno tuo ti edam dah yeht ecnO
,ylla ,tnecer tsom reH
.mottob eht ta ylitsah delbbircs
,ssik drawkwa na otni desserp dna
,tsal ta dias eh ”,haeY“
- ytpme ylraen saw tnaruatser eht hguohtlA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,hctiwta lla sliat dna kcab dial sraE
,yal emoh s’xof regral eht erehw ot
:ssik derovalf-allinav
.etaks a fo kcik eht htiw nehctik eht ot kcab gnimooz erofeb eeffoc fo puc a htob meht deruop ehs
”…taht enod evah t’ndluohs I sseug I
,esaelp ,ekahsklim allinav A“
.keehc eht no ssik a mih evig ot gnimia neeb dah hcihw eno
rehtegot dehsum seson
,owt eht neewteb dekcilf seye ’ssertiaw ehT
,ezag s’rehto eht thguac eh nehw enipluv regral eht deksa ”?taaahW“
,dneirf sih kcab kool ot denrut senipluv eht fo regral ehT
.seicamitni wen gnirolpxe
”?elihw a rof ni emoc ot tnaw uoy od…uoy oD
.koob/di.ylla ta erom nrael nac uoy dna
.elbat eht ssorca mih drawot sserp ot
,deunitnoc noitasrevnoc eht
.yaw eht no htfif a htiw skoob ruof dehsilbup s’ehS
,ecnelis ni gnitae erew owt eht litnu
,tsrif rieht fo scitsigol eht tuo gnikrow
,mets eht yb yletaciled pu ti gnikciP .der thgirb
”,nwonk ev’dluohs I“ ,delbmurg
,ecin gnissikxof ekam taht sgniht elttil eht lla
.txen neppah ot dednetni eh tahw raelc ylriaf saw tI
selzzum gnitiaw otni yaw rieht edam snoops detaoC
- smelborp sih lla ot snoitulos eht ro
,rehtruf elttil a drawrof gninaeL .etarebiled dna
”,tub ,oot od I ,skcuhs ,lleW“
.krowemoh ot stnerap ,seivom
.eeffoc fo efarac a dna ,sgum owt
.nehctik eht sdrawot ffo dehsup dna
,woble sih ta ylthgil gnibbarg
.xof rellams eht deunitnoc ”,og t’nod
.renid eht otni ssalg eht hguorht kcab kool suoituac a evag sexof owt eht
”esuoh eht no“ dna
,spets erom wef a rof ecnelis ni deklaw eH
yaw eht fo tuo si eson eht taht os ylthgils tsuj selzzum gnitlit ekil
,ekahs eht morf noops a debbarg hcae sa
esrevinu eht fo sterces tsepeed eht gnilaever
,kool ypmurg a dna mug reh fo pans a htiW
,ekahs fo gnitaoc larebil a htiw derevoc ydaerla s’noops eht erehw eno taht
,wap ni wap llits
,gninnirg llits ,gnihsulb llitS
,rehtegot delggig
.renid a ,yako ,lleW
,ekahs a gnidloh yart a htiw emit siht
ylippah delims eh ,swap sih no nihc sih gnitseR
,draug ffo thguac
,ffo no detaks dna deddon tacrellor ehT
,xof rellams eht rof hcum ekat t’ndid ti
,llits tas xof rellams eht elihw
si yrots s’yadot dna
.gurhs detaefed a evag neht ,desuap eh
,elims ot wols saw xof rehto ehT
.eno tsenrae na saw ti tub
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”sexoF dna sekahskliM“
noops sih htiw ssalg eht ni dnuora dehsif owt eht fo retrohs eht
.srehtorb erew yeht hguoht sa gnola tog owt eht ,detaler gnieb tuohtiw ralimis kool ot gniganam wohemoS
.rettahc detamina rieht otni kcab gnippils
,rethgual hcum htiW
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,dehsinimid saw ekahs eht ,ylluferac ,ylwolS
.taert eht fo setib wef rehtona mih deef dneirf sih tel eh sa
thgim yeht fi sa retnuoc acimrof eht no sekalf dlog eht ta gnirats elihw eeffoc fo puc dnoces sih gnisrun
.seugnot evitnetta yb naelc dekcil yltneuqesbus dna
.nirg flah a htiw detfil elzzum
esoht fo eno gnieb remotsuc rehto ylno sti
.yawa gninruhc llits saw dnim sih hguoht sa ,ylwols gniddon ,dereffo eh ”,haeY“
:yojne esaelP   .kni.oykam
ssik eht morf kcab dexaler elpuoc eht ,sdnah gnidloh llits
.xof rellat eht ot tuo ti gnidloh
.thgin eht fo tser eht ffo llac dluohs eW“
,yrros m’I“   .ecalp ni nezorf
,selggig fo lluf erew htoB
,noissucsid detamina riehT
,niaga elbat eht ot pu ylhtooms dellor enilef ehT
.s’rehto eht htiw dekcol seye
,xof hcae fo tnorf ni sgum owt eht dna elddim eht ni ekahs eht gnitteS
,etercnoc eht gnola deffucs yeht sa seohs sih ta nwod gnikool saw xof regral ehT .gnihton llitS
,tresed gnitlem ylwols eht ni noops sih deppid dna deggurhs xof eht ,gnihguaL
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.daetsni emoh no dediced yehT
.nwo sih ni sdneirf sih fo htob dloh ot tekcop sih fo eerf wap rehto sih gnippils
.etib derefforp eht ekat ot drawrof denael eh
,hcum sa tsuj gnilimS
snirg htiw dettiftuo
,elbat eht no nwod deppals ,kcehc eht no gnihtemos dettoj ehs
,klawedis eht ta dekcik sexof eht fo rellat ehT .ecnelis ni
,yletarebiled gnivom llits
- tros eht wonk uoy - sloots emorhc-dna-der htiw etelpmoc ,aera epyt rab a htiw dettiftuo era srenid naciremA-elddim esoht fo tsom tuB
,dnoces a rof deremmats owt eht fo rellams ehT
,gniklaw naht gnigdurt erom
.thgil hcrop eht fo wolg tfos eht
,seotpit no gnidnats dna
”?wonk uoy ,sgniht tuoba driew leef tsuj I“
doom laivoj eht no pu dekcip dah ohw
,wodniw eht tuo derats eh sa thguoht ni tsol yltnerappa
”?uoy t’nod ,retteb gnitteg er’yeht kniht I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,od ot retteb gnihtyna fo kcal rof kcehc eht htiw delddif
,etib txen eht sa taht dereffo eh
.stekcop sih nihtiw peed deffuts swap sih
,rehto hcae ta ecnalg ot sexof owt eht gnivael
,semoh owt eht fo resolc eht ,esuoh s’xof regral eht drawot teerts eht nwod ylwols deklaw owt ehT
,niht erew htob hguoht dna ,rehto eht
,gnitaeper erofeb ,deworruf worb
”moor a teg“ dah kcehc ehT
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.tacrellor eht fo ezag lufniadsid eht yb dewollof
swap ykahs s’xof regral ehT
.seye citegolopa htiw secnalg wef a dneirf sih evag xof rellams eht dna
,ti ssorca delwarcs
,nwo sih ni ti gnikat
htoob renroc eht ot yaw rieht edam sdneirf laivoj owt eht
ll’tahW“ .meht ta nwod gnimaeb saw dna
,ssertiaw eht ot pu dennirg sexof ehT
.yllufhsab seye rieht gnitreva erofeb rehto hcae ta delims dna
,dneirf sih htiw pu hctac ot gniyrruh erofeb tnemom a rof llits doots
naht rellat saw enO
,deppots xof rellat ehT   ”.tiaw ,oN“
teerts eht nwod dekool htob neht
,klawedis eht no doots sexof owT
:etib tsrif taht teg ot tuo ti gnillup
devresbo enipluv rellams eht
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,yrrehc eht ta teg ot
,yrros m’I“   .gnihtoN
.tsewhtroN cificaP eht ni rotide dna rohtua na si ohw
,naem I …kniht t’ndid I“
,emit emas eht ta ygolopa na delbmum sexof gnihsulb htoB
,ylteiuq gnilggiG
ot srehcaet morf gnitfird
,desraeher llew ,demialcorp sexof eht fo regral eht ,pu gninethgiartS
nwod dnuow gniklat ehT
,taht ekil drawrof gninael llits tnemyojne ekahs ni rotaripsnoc-oc sih htiW
,dennuts ,xof retrohs ehT
,noitamrof otni lriws wohemos
sdnoces lareves rof ecnelis dennuts ni tas sexof owt ehT
,etisbew reh no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.ecuas etalocohc dna ,maerc deppihw
,delggig htob dna emit emas eht ta rehto hcae ta deggurhs hcaE .sap xuaf fo
.hguone esolc si hcihw
.kram rieht gnittih etiuq ton spil dna
htuom s’xof rellat eht fo renroc eht ta delkcit elims A   ”?ti t’nsaw
”,gnignahc era semiT“
”.thgin eht fo tser eht ffo llac dluohs ew kniht I“
,mets eht morf tiurf teews-oot-tsomla
sexof htob yb derongi tas eeffoc ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
,gnihton dias ehs tub
.reyalp llabteksab eht ,dneirf sih naht rennur kcart a fo erom
.thgin ecin a llits saw ti ,haeY“ .gniddon
.seeffoc dehcuotnu eht llifer ot tnemom enutropponi siht ta pu dellor dah ohw ,ssertiaw eht ot neve raelC
,ezag s’dneirf sih teem ton dluow tub
rallip a pota ssalg eht fo elddim eht ni gnidnats yrrehc onihcsaram eht evael ot erac gnikat hcae
.emoh nabrubus gnuls-wol eht deraen yeht sa
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
wols stnemevom sih
rehto hcae ot ylyhs delims yehT   ”.uoy knahT