.ti ni mih htiw ,tneb fi
.yrd flesmih ekahs ot deirt lacnednelG dna srae sih morf retaw eht gnurw tnecniV elihw
.pird ot desaec sdneirf sih sa moor eht dellif shguoc gnikcah dna
”.niaga ti dnif ll’I dna dnoces a em eviG .taht ekil gnihtemos was I wonk I
.niaga ti odrevo ot ton sa os gnisucof ,elzzum sih nwod derats dna
.raey emas eht ni lla er'ew dna lla uoy naht redlo raey a ylno m’I“
delbmurg tnecniV ”!gnihtemos oD
.ezalba pit-liat sih htiw moor eht dnuora gnimaercs nar gerG
,dexifsnart ,eniotnA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.lla’y ,no emoC“
,sraet hguorht meht fo lla ta detuohs gerG
eno otni tsurht yltneloiv saw tneduts hcae dna sevlesmeht dethgir sriahc dna skseD
.denruter noisserpxe sseltsil sih dna
.moc.seicehporPeriD no gnitirw sih tuo kcehC
.mih koohs dna ,sredluohs eht yb mih debbarg ,eniotnA ot pu nar ,nekcirts ,gerG
nezorf mih gnivael
”!gnizama saw tahT“
”!tuo dnif syawla yeht tuB“
”!nwod teg enoyrevE“
,retpecs nedoow eht fo pot eht ta
pans taerg a ekil dnuos a htiw htinez sti dehcaer lleps eht
.noisserpxe gnidnammoc a htiw erif eht ot revo dehsur dna
,pu kool ot hguone elbatrofmoc
.noitneted ni ydaerla er’eW
.riah fo sdnarts nworb-ydnas edisa dehsurb ehs sa
”!noitneted fo tuo teg reven ll’eW !esaelp ,on ,enoitnA“
”?looc gnihtyna dniF“
”,tropsliops a hcus eb t’noD“
,ksed sih dniheb tas dna
.gerG dias ”,ti yrt tsuj ,si ti revetahW“
,rehtegot kcab saw egac s’lacnednelG nevE
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
gnimmiws dekcimim ehS
tnempiuqe dna skooB
.keew tsal deiduts ew seno dniw eht fo eno htiw lleps erif eht devaewretni I“
,retpecs eht ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut tub ,seye sih dellor eniotnA ”!redrah kooL“
.noitatnacni s’lleps eht nageb dna
eniotnA delkcuhc ”,hcum oot yrrow uoY“
.mmH“ .noitnetta neddus eht ta hcrep sih no ylsuovren detfihs ohw esidarap-fo-drib deroloc-ylthgirb ,ylurnu eht
.seog ereh ,thgirlA“ ”.noos
.deggurhs meht fo tser ehT
eniotnA ta yltnatcepxe gnikool
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.pu mih gnidloh ,gerG dias
,retpecs eht ot denruter eniotnA
.daeherof sih debbur dna dehgis gerG
ygrene sti htiw gnillews moor eht leef dluoc meht fo hcae
selzzum rieht depacse stuohs dekcinaP
,detnalp swap htiw ksed reh revo gninael ,anayrA deksa
wap sih kcab dellup tnecniV
,lleW“ .rae na dniheb gnihctarcs ,anayrA dettimda ”,rehtie eM“
,deliaf dah lleps eht erus saw hcae tnemom a roF
.ylteiuq detnahc dna
,wap sih fo noitom eht dewollof dna demrof thgil fo sliart etihw dna eulB
seye sih revo nwod srae sih dellup tnecniV
,eriD yb ”srekaM feihcsiM“
.ygrene htiw deslup taht sduolc dna retaw fo sgnir otni gnimrofsnart
swap htob htiw ylthgit retpecs eht deppirg eniotnA ”.seog
”!on ,eniotnA .oN“
,nageb yeht nehw neeb dah ti erehw ot denruter moorssalc elohw ehT
,drawrof dekrep srae s’anayrA
”!keew siht yad yreve noitneted ni neeb ev’ew yhw s’tahT“ .gerG denihw
,rewop ym gnillortnoc no krow ot deen I“ .eniotnA desum ”,riahc sih fo tuo mih gnihsup fo daetsni wodniw eht tuo nacnuD dessot ew tluaf ym ton s’tI“
”.detrats teg ylbaborp dluohs ew ,lleW“
dengila stnemges lleps etacirtni eht
.niaga ecno lluf saw ti litnu werger ruf eht dna knip ot der
,tnecniV ot lacnednelG ffo gnidnah ,gerG ”!siht od
”!uoy htiw gnorw s’tahW“ ”.niaga ti oD
s’teL“ .eniotnA demialcxe ”!seY“ ”.cigam
.ksed s’notlaD rosseforP ffo retpecs gniniart eht detfil xof-
tniop egatnav detrevni sih morf dna ,ediw denepo rood moorssalc ehT
sregnif sih deppans notlaD rosseforP
htaeneb dnuorg eht otni roolf doow-tals eht hguorht gnikael dehsinif retaw laudiser ehT
!siht xif ot gnihtemos oD“
.tsehc sih ot pit-liat dekaos dna dehcrocs sih gnigguh
”.krow yllautca lliw taht gnihtemos dnif ot yrt I elihw mih fo dloh a peeK“
”.elbuort otni teg ot gniog er’eW“
.retpecs eht hguorht detnuh ylirgnuh
.cigam fo epyt siht ta retteb m’I
dessergorp lleps eht sA
”.siht xif ot gnihtemos dnif I elihw ykwauqS llits ,anayrA .ezeej ,gniddehs trats ot deen oN
.gerG derettups ”!snoitucexe eht ot thgiarts og dna
”,ees annaw I ,oot eM“
.paeh fo tib a ni dna tnrub dna tew llits fi sevlehs rieht ot denruter
”,tik gib ay ,enif eb ll’uoy hO“
.gerG detsetorp ”!on ,eniotnA“
.reh deirrac stnerruc lacigam eht sa
.nrut ni meht fo hcae ta dekool eH
”!enasni gnieb ton fo esnes a evah uoy t’nod yhW“
gnihsilbatse m’I“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
notlaD rosseforP ,swap sih gnitfiL
larips nepo devrac yletanro eht otni peed dereep eniotnA
.sdaeh rieht koohs lla yehT .eniotnA deksa
seye sih desiar flow ehT
sevlesmeht deisub anayrA dna tnecniV elihw lacnednelG no dloh sih peek ot delggurts gerG
!emosewA .saW .tahT“
.ti evoba rehto eht gnilcric
.bro lufraef hcae nihtiw gnigar thgil gninrub eht
.roolf eht ffo pu esidarap-fo-drib detneirosid eht depoocs gerG sa
sgnir eht morf detpure sduolc gniwollib kraD
”.meht sllet eno on fi
morf denrut niks eht sa thgil etihw a htiw dewolg pit-liat siH
.lacitpeks gnikool ,gerG dias ”,ees emmeL“
,deirt dah yeht lleps eht detaeper
”.yltcaxe ,si ti fo tser eht tahw erus ton m’I .esrever ni wolf ot secruos
”.llits dloh woN .skcab-emoc ruoy no krow ot deen uoY“
.kcor tresed a fo edis denrut-nus eht naht reyrd
retpecs dehctertstuo eht fo dne eht ta derats lacnednelG
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.tnemom a ni spahreP“
.gerG ot revo yaw reh gnihsalps ,anayrA dedlocs
.eniotnA ot denrut anayrA
.deltsirb liat sih dna
.daehrevo yllacitarre welf eh sa lacnednelG no ezag reh dekcol ehs sa anayrA dias ”,erusaelp yM“
?tuo railimaf sih tel uoy fi tuo dnif ton notlaD rosseforP dluoc woH“
dedisbus tsug eht sA
.nirg a htiw deggaw eniotnA
.retpecs eht dnuora dedworc lla yeht sa suoiruc dekool tnecniV nevE .anayrA dedda
,eniotnA dias ”,lla’y ,swen dab
”.ti htiw yalp s’teL
”,ecnahc tseb ruo s’ti ekil sdnuoS“
.moor eht dennacs dna
flow elbarenev eht thguac eh thguoht eniotnA
rehtegot resolc dna resolc swap nepo reh thguorb ylwols ehs ,seye reh gniworraN
.detcennoc yeht sa naorg a htiw
,ylivaeh gnihgis ,tnecniV
”.erutnevda fo esnes a evaH“
,palc gnitanoser a htiW
stneduts sih gnieye
nuf evah ot uoy tnaw reven stludA“ .dennirg eniotnA
.gnitapissid erofeb moorssalc eritne eht gnihcnerd dna semalf eht gnisuod ,nageb ruopnwod laitnerrot a retal tnemom A
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,eriD yb
si sihT“ .dehgual anayrA
.seirots-trohs yrruf lareves dna levon a no gnikrow yltnerruc si ohw
.degnahcnu noisserpxe sih ,tnecniV dehgis
.noitatnacni eht ekops eniotnA sa
.mih ta delims tsuj anayrA
.moor eht tfel dna
.htrof dna kcab deppihw ti sa liat reh htiw tnecniV gnikirts ylraen
lleps eht tsac eniotnA erom ecirhT
liat s’gerG revo swap reh dleh anayrA
reh deknaht ylgnigdurg gerG
.semalf eht fo yaw eht fo tuo teg ot
.seerga tnecniV ?eeS“
”?su morf tpek ev’yeht gnihtynA“
.tsedlo eht er’uoY“
.kcab dial srae dna nwod selzzum rieht ,ezag sih nruter t’ndluow ohw
!thgirla ,thgirlA“ ”!woN
seye neerg sih sa ekops
.ti od em tel tub ,thgirlA“
.gerG detuohs ”!yrros yllaer er’eW“
.htgnel devruc sti nihtiw dleh slleps derots eht rehpiced ot gniyrt
.dekaeuqs eciov s’nooccar eht
”.dellepxe gnitteg si eno oN“
.ezingocer t’ndid eh eno dnuof eh litnu slleps derots eht hguorht gninnacs
”.ti fo strap dnatsrednu I
.egac eht ta mia koot dna
”.won gnitrats ,ti gnigrahc ereh ,txen dna ,keew siht gnineve hcae dneps lliw uoY
.ria eht otni swap reh tohs anayrA
.ti tog ev’I kniht I“
”.’eniotnA decaf-tna‘ em gnillac neeb evah t’ndluohs eh dna
.gnirekcins ,tnecniV dias
drow noitatnacni elgnis eht delahxe eh sA
.eniotnA dedda ”,thgir s’ehS“
.ylkciuq ecalper ot evisnepxe
.deunitnoc soahc gninruhc eht sa ti deiduts eH
.yltneloiv deglub dna dewolg egac ehT
.raew rof esrow tsuj
”?elbuort erom naem uoy t’noD“
.sevlesmeht ot lla cigam eht peek ot tnaw yeht esuaceb
”?si noitar-galf-noc a tahw aedi ynA“
.eniotnA ta delwocs gerG ”?nuF“
”.lasrever fo klat htiw efir si ereh ni lleps xelpmoc tsom ehT
”.ti fo yna tuo ekam t’nac I“ .eniotnA deksa
.shguoc nwo sih neewteb yldeticxe eniotnA demialcxe ”!dekrow tI“
”!lacnednelG tog I“
sgnir eht fo retnec eht hguorht pu ti debbaj erofeb raeps a ekil ti dleh dna
.wap sih ni deraeppa retpecs gniniart eht dna
.ot deliaf dah tpmetta rieht gnihtyreve gnidnem dna gnithgir
.eniotnA dias ”!gniog dooG“
”.ytilibained elbisualp
eriD yb ”srekaM feihcsiM“   :yojne esaelP
.sraet fo egrev eht no gerG dias ”,gnihtemos eb ot tog s’erehT“
.elzzum sih ssorca yaw sti gnikrow nirg yls a
.doow delioc eht morf detpure
moor eht fo tnorf eht ot ylmlac deklaw notlaD rosseforP
.ti ekorb gerG litnu detsisrep ecnelis ytliug rieht neht neve dna
.erus eb t’ndluoc eh tub ,detrons eh nehw gninnirg
.moor eht detcepsni dna ksed eht rednu morf tuo emac anayrA
.noitom fo yrrulf eht ni pu tpews erew yeht sa
”?siht dnatsrednu enoyna seoD“
.noos kcab eb lliw notlaD rosseforP“
”?ffuts skcolnu taht ereht ni gnihtyna ereht sI“
,retpecs gniniart eht ta derats eniotnA
si hcihw ,retpecs gniniart eht morf egrahc fo laed taerg a niard slleps decnavdA“
”,htaerb ruoy gnitsaw er’uoY“
.ruf rieht gnimat htiw
.tnemtnioppasid ni kcab deyalps srae sih
.noisserpxe elbarovafnu na dna worbeye desiar a htiw
”?emit siht erus uoy erA“ .eniotnA dias
,retpecs gniniart eht tuohtiw tub
tlef enoyna erofeb elihw a saw tI
derettahs egac eht erofeb tsuj dekcud lla yehT .enoitnA detuohs
tuo dnif t’now yehT
”,ebyam ,retsasid larutan A“ ”.larutan a m’I“
erif dna dnim sih ni meht depahs dah eniotnA sa tsuj
.gniliec eht ssorca tuo dna pu dehsur dna
”.rehtegot kcab egac eht tup nac taht ereh ni gnihtyna dnif t’nac I“
?raey artxe taht htiw daeh eht revo mih taeb ,od ot desoppus I ma tahW
ksed reh rednu deirrucs anayrA
”.tey ot nettog t’nevah ew taht ereh ni slleps ynam os era erehT !woW !haeY“
,hsarc suorednuht a htiw snoitcerid lla ni sdrawtuo delruh erew stnanmer sti dna
”.delaes yllacigam si egac tahT
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,rewop hcum oot llitS“
,retpecs eht ta derats eh sa eniotnA detnemal
elzzum s’gerG fo tuo sdrow tsal eht htiW
.ereht meht dleh dna
”!em ta kooL !emosewa
.tnecniV ot txen detaes nexiv derruf-der eht ,anayrA dias
.noisserpxe derob a htiw ksed sih ta gnittis erah etihw-dna-nworb eht deksa
,thgilf-dim noitom s’drib eht detlah hcihw thgil neerg fo tsrub a ni rehtegot swap reh thguorb ehs
”.nuf emos gnivah tsuj er’eW“
.ecitcarp…siht llac tsuj s’teL ?thgir ,retpecs gniniart eht s’ti ,sediseB
.rae sih dniheb morf tnecniV deksa ”?tey revo ti sI“
der deye-thgirb ehT
.stnemges noitaretla dna ,ecnesse ,gnidnib rieht era ereht eerht esoht dna ,htrae fo scinagro dna scillatem eht rof slobmys eht era owt esohT ?eseht eeS“ .retpecs eht fo ecafrus eht no detaolf taht senur laerehte fo reyal a ot detniop gerG
sebor ymedaca sih fo seveels eulb-dna-etihw ywollib eht kcab dellup eh sa
.sebor sih ot gnulc taht semalf eht ta yldliw dewap dna retpecs eht deppord eniotnA ,pley a htiW
,yllacitnarf gerG dedaelp ”!tnecniV“
.ysaenu meht edam ti litnu
mih ta kcab gnirats notlaD rosseforP nwod-edispu na was eniotnA
.gnihtemos otno barg ot yllufsseccusnu deirt dna delialf eh sa gerG detuohs ”!od I did tahW !od I did tahW“
ria fo tsrub a yb ffo tuc erew sdrow reH ”-ew od tahw oS“
.yldeticxe gnicnuob ,eniotnA detuohs ”!syug yeH“
”!rosseforp ,su pleH“
moor eht ni gnihtyreve neht
!meht neve ,evom ot nageb ylwols
”.noitneted hcum siht tuoba nuf gnihton s’erehT“
.ria eht hguorht gnitaolf dna
.ecnatsid eht otni tuo deohce taht
tnemges rieht wolla taht slennahc lufrewop hcae era htaenrednu reyal siht ni senur fo stes eht dnA
.yldeirrow gerG deksa
.yrd enob taorht reh ,tif gnihguoc a yb nekat saw ehs
”.llits dloH .tnecniV .gerG
,pu mlap wap eno dleh erah ehT
.noitatnacni gnillits eht delbmum ehs sa
htgnerts sih derehtag
doots notlaD rosseforP
.nihtiw drib gnikwauqs eht gnieerf
.repmihw duol a htiw regnif sih werdhtiw yltnatsni dna pit-liat sselruf sih detset nooccar ehT
”.ti htiw yalp s’teL“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.tuo ykwauqS kaerb dluohs uoY“
”.netfo os ereh eb ot stneduts detacided yrev eb tsum uoY“
noislupxe eht piks ot gniog er’yehT !od uoy did tahW“
”srekaM feihcsiM“ saw sihT
.slleps sti dehcraes eh sa ,deworruf worb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
deglub seye s’gerG
srae sih kcab debmoc
,lacnednelG ot denrut seye llA
”!dellepxe teg ot gniog er’ew retpecs gniniart eht htiw dnuora gnissem er’uoy dna kcab semoc notlaD rosseforP fI
,hhU“ .noitcafsitas ni swap reh detsud anayrA ”.enod dna enoD“
.sessalg demmir-eriw hguorht troppus rof setamssalc dna sdneirf rehto sih ot dekool nooccar tuots ehT
,ediw tnew seye s’enoyrevE
”.gnihtemos gniod ma I ,sediseB
.noitatnacni eht detuohs eh sa