dehctircs retto eht dna
,gel s'retto eht no wap etihw a gnitteS ".pag
.taht ekil saw dneirfyob dnoces yM
.pots t’ndid naedeaN tub
rood eht denepo naedeaN ,rednaw ot nageb ylurt dnim sih erofeb tsuJ
;gninialpmoc pots woN
,deppots yllanif wap sih nehw dnA
.pohs retfa pohs tsap klaw reh dehctaw eh sa delims tibbar ehT
.drawrof denael ehs ,htrof dna kcab gnidils llitS
.srexob sih ni mih gnivael
.ti ni tsol teg dluoc eh taht hguone euqinu tub
.uoy htiw yaw sih sah eh elihw llaw eht tsniaga uoy hsup ot hguone gnortS"
.kcen s'retto eht gnilzzun ,dias tibbar eht
.delggig retto ehT ".sgnihtyalp
.taorht reh deraelc dna
”.toh si“ ,ecap eht pu gnipeek ,deffuh ehs
.denoitnem ynneJ pu-revoc enilucsam rehtona fo yarps a ti evag dna riap redlo renaelc a debbarg I
.mih ta nwod gnilims ,dias ehs ”,taht deyojne uoy ekil kool uoY“
.retto eht ot resolc dils nodnarB ".ecneirepxe
.pu dekrow htob meht dah xes fo klat tnatsnoc eht tub
mih edisni nottub erusaelp citsatnaf taht tsniaga gnisserp dna skeehc sih neewteb gnidils kcoc eht fo tsurht hcaE
,ni delttes saw eh retfA
,kcab pets a koot ehS
.niorg reh ot wap reh deppord retto ehT
”.niaga sgel ruoy em eviG“
,erow revol sih srexob eht no dekcol dnim sih sA
.spil eht no mih dessik dna keehc sih deppuc ehs
.reduol werg snaom sih ,s’nodnarB tem
".elttil a ti egdun depleh I ebyaM"
.taert a eb ylniatrec dluow ti
.spil eht no mih dessik ehS
"?naedeaN ,gnitcejorp t'nera uoy erus uoy erA"
,deksa ehs
.emit eritne eht desolc seye
.derepsihw retto eht ",taes a evaH"
,suoitcefni saw hgual reH
.rae sih ni welb dna ni denael ehs
.meht ediseb ti tes dna ebul fo elttob a tuo dellup ehs ,reward a morF
,pets reh ni piks a fo tib a htiW
roolf eht no lewot eht deppord ehS
,esirprus ni depsag tibbar ehT
.ssik rehtona rof ni reh dellup dna
.ffo meht llup ot kcab dial dna
”.tops eht tih taht ,noh ,yllaeR“
.niaga naom ot nageb eh
,diuqil kcils eht fo spmup llams owt gnitcelloc retfA
strohs sih denottubnu ehs ,tib a kcab mih gnihsuP
”?tnemom a em evig dna niaga deb eht no taes a ekat uoy t’nod yhW“
.trihs reh gnippirg ,denaom nodnarB
?ti ta kool annog tsuj uoy erA“
”.siht gniyojne eb yllaer ot mees uoy“
,roolf eht no raewrednu sih deppord ehs sA
depruls eH ”.ees I“ .deilper nodnarB ”,hA“ ”.gib oN .ynneJ gnitxet tsuJ“ .delims retto ehT ”?tuoba saw txet ylemit taht tahw ksa I yaM“
”.gninrom eht ni flesruoy reh knaht nac uoy dnA .ot yppah eb d’I“
”.ybab ,dliw em gnivird si kcoc er’uoY .esolc os m’I
,pih s’retto eht no wap a gnipeeK
,deb eht fo egde eht ot yaw sih demriuqs nodnarB
,selkna sih no taeh ydob reh tlef dna eman reh denaom eh sA ”.naeD hO“
?yako ,gninialpmoc oN"
,seye sih fo llor citamard a htiW ".epytoerets
.noitcelloc ruoy nees ev’I dna gnol sehcni xis ylno s’ti ,sediseB
,tnemeticxe sih ni deb eht tsniaga srae sih gnikcams ,deddon tibbar ehT
.revol reh ta derats retto eht
”.erom esaeler sih gnillems neeb htob ev’ew ,naem I
”sgnileeF dessiM“ saw sihT
.deb eht no kcab gnippolf dna
.elbat edisdeb eht ot devom dna
,tsehc sih nwod swap reh dedilg ehS ".snalp
.ecnartne sih htiw pu pit eht denil neht
,sredluohs reh no meht tes ehs ,emit a ta enO
.niaga spil eht no mih dekcep retto ehT ".nialpmoc
”.skool rof tsuj t’nia siht ,sediseB“
.yawa thgir mih dnuof dna seye sih dewollof retto ehT "?mih tuoba woH"
.enihw llams a tuo tel nodnarB dna
tuhs seye sih dewercs nodnarB ”!naeD hO“
,pu srexob eht fo cirbaf eht gnihsup ,ti dnoyeb dna dnuora stigid sih lruc ot detrats eH
.spil sih daerps eh dna ,s’naedeaN ot spil sih desserp nodnarB ,emoh tog yeht dnoces eht dnA
ezeeuqs eltneg a htiw drow eht detautcnup ehS ".moordeb
raer sih morf tfahs eht lla tsomla dellup ehs
”?eaN ,esroh a yhw oS“
,spih sih deyaws nodnarB
.elbbird a ot gniwols erofeb semit ruof ,eerht
redrah kniht ot htob
,esroh a ot no dekcol ezag siH
.uoy ot detacided m'I ,uoy htiw m'I elihw
”.thgirla ,thgirlA“ .delkcuhc naedeaN
,llems eht dna ,thgis eht ,noitom eht neewteB
”.pots ro nwod wols ll’I dna drow eht yas tsuj uoy ,kciuq ot sevom gnihtyna fi tuB .lliw I“
.kcab dellup naedeaN
.kcab gnillup yllanif erofeb
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ecnad eht del eugnot reh ,emit sihT
.niaga reh ta pu dekool nodnarB
ni deklaw retto ehT
.ydob s’retto eht gnola
stigid reh devruc ehS ”?erus uoY“
.od ot gniyrt er’uoy tahw wonk I tub ,yrt eciN“
,thgil deniamer noitasrevnoc rieht ,trap tsom eht roF
”.sevol eh elpoep eht tsuJ
.deppots retto ehT ”.naeD esaelP
.tfahs sih morf tpael dees fo tohs tsrif eht sa
,uoy roF" ".ydaer mees uoY"
”?noitnetta emos ti evig emoc rO
”,hcum os em esaet t’nod ,naeD hO“
.elims saw od dluoc ehs llA
,did uoy ebyaM" .delims naedeaN
.ssergit a ot gniddon
,dluoc ehs sa yltnelis sa ,dnA
,emarf rellams reh dnuora parw ot deirt swap sih nehW
.erom demriuqs tibbar ehT
.srexob sih fo riap depirts-neerg a dna
.gninrom eht ni krow evah dna derit er’uoY
,meht neewteb wap dna tfahs sih gnippart ,nwod denael ehS
tuo deirc eh ”!gniog peeK“
naedeaN dnuora smra sih depparw tibbar eht ,sredluohs sih htob revo dehcaer swap reh nehW
,yaw eht gnola selppin s’tibbar eht gnikcilf
.spih s’naedeaN dnuora daerps sgel sih sa deredduhs nodnarB .deb
.srexob sih ot ezag sih werd reh ot resolc pets hcaE
.htaerb gninaom rehtona koot eh sa deddon tibbar eht
ylthgils denepo seye siH
.srexob sih ni deppart llits
,pu kcab stigid reh deliart ehS
,deb rieht yb erew yeht ecnO
",retto na fo noisserpmi doog a od uoY"
,era uoy fi ti yrt ot nwod llits m’I
emoC“ .drawrof mih degaruocne dna
.sregnif reh deppans ehs ,retal tnemom a dnA
’sserP xoF deruomrA ni deraeppa tsrif yrots siH
.mih tsniaga denael naedeaN
.srexob sih otni gnisaet
rehto sih ni tfahs eht dleh eh
.spih reh dnuora selkna sih depparw eh sa niaga pil sih tib nodnarB
.ssik eht ekorb dna
”?kniht uoy t’nod ,em rof gib elttil a skool ti tuB .riaf s’tahT“
.htuom reh otni eugnot sih gnittel ,dnik ni dednopser naedeaN
,ylwols detrats eH
.tibbar eht edisni yaw sti delggiw ti
.yteicos rof ksam a s'tahT
.eson reh no ynneJ dessik ehS
,elzzum sih ni tfahs eht flah revo dah eh ecnO
.ecaf reh tfel reven elims yoc ehT
”.tcefrep saw yot tahT .ynneJ ,thgir erew uoy dnA .haey hO“
,gnorw em teg t’noD“ .reh ta wap sih devaw eH
,nageb ehs erofeB
.flac sih dessik naedeaN
,edis ot edis morf spih reh delggiw ehS
.sgnihtyalp reh gnidnammoc ,porc gnidir a seirrac dna rehtael snod ylbaborP
”.kcoc ym ekil uoy hcum woh em wohS .yenoh ,no emoC“
.epytoerets gniklaw a tsomla er’uoY
.redluohs reh no sgel sih derevuenam dna
.gnihton saw ti ekil deggurhs retto ehT
tuoba tahW"   edniM JT yb
”.ecitne dna esuora ot gnihtemoS
,sedis dehctiws dna reh ta dekool eh ,nwod yawflaH
.daeh sih gnikahs ,derettum eh ”,lrig tahT“
.trihs a debbarg dna
.tiaw dna deb eht no kcab polf dna
# .gniklaw erew yeht noitcerid eht ni daeh reh gniddon
,niorg s’retto eht ot tog eh resolc eht dna ni koot eh erom eht tub ,tib a noisremmi eht ekorb
.daeherof dna seye sih ssorca detser mra rehto sih sa skaeuqs fo seires a tuo tel tibbar ehT
.dnuora pilf ot sinep enocilis eht gnisuac
rednaw ot nageb dnah reh sa keehc s’retto eht delzzun dna ni denael ehS
,liat sih rednu tnemrag eht dekooh dna
.s’retto eht tsniaga pmub dna llews kcoc nwo sih gnikam ,dexelf nodnarB
.ydaer tog retto eht sa wap sih ni debborht kcoc s’tibbar ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,mih otni tfahs eht fo erom desserp ehs ,drawrof pets a flah gnikat retfA
”.em tuoba yrrow t’nod dias I dnA
.ssik eht ekorb ehs
,sgel sih fo kcik a htiW
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.hguoht ,uoy tuoba tahW“
.nodnarB ta decnalg ehs sa elims a otni devruc htuom reh fo srenroc ehT ".neeuq
.deddon nodnarB ”.yakO“
,emit sihT "?mih dnA"
.daeh sih fo pot eht dessik ehS
,denruter ehs ,retal stnemoM
.dah ydaerla I gnihtemos s’tI .yrrow t’noD“
.thgir elttil a er'uoY .enif ,eniF"
.daeh sih revo dna ffo dellup saw elcitra eht
”.flesmih deyojne eh dalg m’I
”?uoy t’nod ,taht ekil yllaer uoY“
,eson sih dessik ehs dna
,deb eht ediseb mih yb gnidnatS
”.ti tnaw I ,esaelP“
”.siht otni teg nac I ebyam ,yakO“
,mih gnillif kcoc kciht eht htiw dekcap ,tnecs enilucsam taht htiw yvaeh
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.elkcunk dnoces eht ta tsrif eht denioj ti tub
,nihc reh ot wap a tes ehS
.elzzum eht no drah tibbar eht dessik dna
.reh denioj tibbar eht dna
.erutinruf eht ediseb sfeirb eht deppord ehS
?esuolb reh ni skool ehs ylrig woh eeS"
,dekaerc deb eht nehW
.pal sih ffo dils neht
.ydob dekan sih revo dna pu srevoc eht dellup tibbar ehT
gnitnap ,niaga eye sih desolc eH
ydob s’retto eht dnuora sgel sih depparw eh
.neewteb ni erehwyreve dna egadnob ot laro morF
.moorhtab eht ot yaw reh edam dna dnuora kcab denrut ehs
.ssa ruoy pu kcoc a ekat uoy sa ekam uoy snaom tfos eht draeH
”?gniog uoy era erehW“
.mih ta nwod dna pu dekool naedeaN
,GNAF ni dehsilbup neeb s’ohw renniW drawA yraretiL oeL a
.deb eht ffo dils tibbar ehT
.tif ti ekam nac ew teb I“
taht rof gnihcraes
spih reh no swap sih tes tibbar ehT
,emit sihT ".htob rO"
”?ew llahS“ .yawa htob werht dna nac hsart a ot deklaw ehs
.dneirfyob reh delddarts ylwols retto eht ,rehtegot desserp erew selzzum rieht elihw dnA
,htgnel s’tibbar eht tsniaga ti dehsup dna yot eht ot tuo wap a dehcaer naedeaN
-- em ni kcid a fo gnileef eht ssim I
.hctorc sih yb mih gnidael erofeb
,hguorht emac pit eht sA
.eno htiw gniyalp ni detseretni dednuos uoy dnA“
.kcoc sih gnola wap a edils ot nageb ehs
,elkcuhc a tuo deffuh nodnarB
”.uoy rof hcterts elttil a eb ylno dluohs sihT
;stsaerb reh edih ot hguone egral saw trihs ehT
.pag eht llif ot gniyrt neeb ev'I ,sey ,dnA
,reh morf yawa ecap-a-flah doots eh ecnO
seye reh desolc retto ehT
,spih reh gnivom deunitnoc dna
.sreh fo tib tsal eht nwod dekcus naedeaN ”?uoY .gniog peek ot ydaer m’I kniht I“ .reniatnoc eht koohs dna knird sih fo tsal eht
.ecaf s’retto eht ta tub
.sgel reh neewteb kcid eht fo thgis eht ni gnikat
”?evisnepxe yllausu esoht t’nerA“
.tnemeerga ni deddon eh sa debbob srae kcalb gnol s’nodnarB
.edis ot edis morf spih reh gnigniws
.hgiht sih gnola kcab tfahs reh dils ehs neht
”.reh fo kniht srehto tahw fo deracs elttil a dna devreseR
,dnabtsiaw sih fo citsale eht ta desaet ehS
.elzzum sih ni tfahs eht gnikat detrats nodnarB
”,eaN ,uoy evol I“ .dias retto ehT
.deggurhs tibbar ehT
.enecs eht ot dedda ereht cirbaf eht gniees dnA
,llam eht hguorht deklaw yeht sa senot dehsuh ni deunitnoc emag riehT
,reh fo edis rehtie ot dial llits sgel siH
s’tibbar eht ediseb kcoc esroh eht detser naedeaN
.wap no siht evah ot deneppah I dnA
.deggeb eh sa erised ni retrofmoc eht deppirg nodnarB
;eaN ,em wonk uoy tuB“
.ylf eht denottubnu dna nwod dehcaer ehS
.eye eno htiw retto eht ees ot hguone mra sih gnivom
.rood eht desolc dna moorhtab eht otni deppils retto eht
,ssik eht ni tsol tog nodnarB elihw dnA
.nosrep a ot dehcatta ,eno laer a
.tnecs eht no desucof dna
.maor ot nageb wap eerf sih dna
.tcepxe d'uoy gnihtyreve s'eh ,hO"
"?neht ydaer teg og I tuoba woH"
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.spih reh gnivom llits ,deksa ehS
.enohp reh tuo gnillup ,dias ehs
.reh ot pu dekool eh
.htaerb esirprus a htiw ssik eht kaerb tibbar eht gnikam ,niorg mrif sih ot devom eno dna
daeh sih dniheb stigid sih gnical erofeb htgnel sih gnola wap sih nar tibbar ehT ".yddub
.tsehc yssem sih ta
.pu uoy krow dluoc ezeerb ffits doog a denrael ev'I
,sedis reh no swap sih htiW
.dekrow taht ecap a nwod lian em depleh taht eno eht s’ehS
.tfahs taht dnA
,dessik yeht regnol ehT
”.mmhM“ ”.llew dekrow ti ekil skool dnA
.lasuora retfos nwo s’retto eht htiw dexim esle gnihtemos did os tub ,eson sih dedoolf tnecs nwo siH
tsuj I tub ,siht did ew semit rehto eht devol ev’I
.pirg sih fo tuo gnilggiw ,dias retto eht ”,thgir er’uoY“
,htrof dna kcaB .gniddon
.derewsna eciov a ”,ni emoC“
.nialpmoc em gniraeh eb t'now uoY"
”.yug a saw I dneterp dluoc eh os srexob sih fo riap a htiw ti edih ot dah I .mrahc a ekiL“
”.tsrif sgniht tsrif ,tuB“
.yltfos denaom dna
,mih rof erots ni saw tahw erus t'nsaw eh elihw dnA
.tsenrae ni flesmih gnirusaelp nageb tfahs sih dnuora wap sih dna reh fo og tel tibbar ehT
.erugif reh gniksam srexob dialp-dna-neerg
,yzah saw ezag siH
.sdrow reh ksam dna
.taht ekil semit rof stifeneb htiw dneirf a dnif t’nseod eh yhw ees t’nod tsuj I“
.moor eht fo tuo gniklaw ,dias ehs
.tas yeht erehw dexelf dna nwod knird sih tes nodnarB ".tcepxe
.gel sih detfil rehto eht elihw tfahs sih no wap reh tes retto eht ,drow a tuohtiW
”?gniod uoy era tahw won dnA“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
deddon tsuj tibbar eht ,emit sihT .deksa naedeaN
– stib tnatropmi eht gnisopxe tub kcas sih gnidih srexob eht dna
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
”sgnileeF dessiM“:yojne esaelP
”.hcum os uoy knahT“
elzzum reh ssorca ekorb nirg yls A
”.rof ksa uoy tahw luferac eB .thgirlA“
”.naeD ,ereht tsomla m’I .erom ,esaelP“
,dekrow eugnot reh sa dnA
dna trihs-t yarg eht ,redluohs reh tsniaga gnitser saw gel eno :krow reh dehctaw tibbar ehT .dekaeuqs nodnarB ,ti dnuof ehs ecno dnA
daeh sih fo kcab eht no wap a tes naedeaN .esle gnihtemos
.daeh reh koohs retto ehT
.rewsna dluoc eh erofeb doots ehS
”.ti worrob em gnittel rof sknahT
tfahs nwo sih evoba gnirevoh ylerab tsuj saw kcoc esroh eht ,elgna siht morF
.arb on htiw yawrood eht ni doots retto ehT .pu tas nodnarB
.eegilgen tnerapsnart ,niht a erow dna sdnah reh ni koob a dah ehS
,meht neewteb ecnatsid thgils eht ta gniratS
.delims dna eltit eht thguac naedeaN
".namow a no riap ecin a ekil uoy naht erom oN
.elzzum reh ssorca deirrac ehs elims eht ot hctorc reh morf derats nodnarB
"?ti t'nsi ,won retteb elttil a s'tahT"
.ecneirepxe dlrow-laer elttil yrev dah s'ehS
”.snalp evah I ebyaM“
.esirprus kcom ni htuom reh revo wap reh daerps dna deffocs ehS
.truoc doof eht sdrawot
,srexob eht otni gnihcaer ,nehT
.erdnetne elbuod eht ta delggig htob yeht dna desuap eH
resserd s’tibbar eht ot thgir deklaw dna denruter ehs ,retal etunim a naht sseL
.yawa mih degdun dna redluohs sih no wap a tes naedeaN tub
.tnemeticxe sih ta elkcuhc tub pleh t’ndluoc retto ehT ”?esaelP“
kcab deppets retto ehT
.elddim s’eod eht gnola lairetam niht eht revo stigid reh decnad ehS
.erusaelp fo elcsum hguot
.noitcerid eht gnidnatsrednu ,deddon nodnarB
.htaerb peed a koot dna ylf eht ot elzzum sih desserp dna
.naom a dleh eh sa tfahs sih gnola hsalf a saw wap siH ”!semoc ti ereH“
.trapa htdiw redluohs sgel reh daerps retto eht
,tekcop reh otni kcab enohp reh dils ehs retfA ".taht
,kniw kciuq a htiW
.arb reh gnipsalcnu ,trihs reh rednu dils swap siH
”?em rof reh knaht nac uoy ebyam ,lleW“ .deddon nodnarB
.eglub ecin a ekil I fi ti pleh t'nac I ,naem I"
,ecap eltneg ,wols a gnitteS
,decnad seugnot rieht sA
”.denaelc neeb s’ti ,ksa uoy erofeb ,sey dnA
.noitceffa eht gninruter
.mih otni stigid reh dils retto eht
.moorhtab eht fo tuo deppets ehs sa peels peed
.toof reh htiw desolc yltsom rood eht gnigdun
".deb ym ni rehtona evah ot erised on evah I dnA
.ruf pmad yb dednuorrus noitcere mrif sih saw
,troffe erom elttil a koot dnoces ehT
htiw dexim tnemrag eht no flesmih fo tnecs eht ta dehctiwt eson siH
wap reh ni sfeirb desu dna yot denaelc eht deirrac dna ydob reh dnuora depparw lewot a erow ehS
.liat reh gnicart ,tsiaw reh dnuora citsale eht ot neht
.tnemeticxe dna ssensuovren htob ni
”.ecnahc a em evig tsuJ“
”?ffo emoc ot eseht rof ydaer uoY“
.teiuq dna hsikoob s'ehs ,hO"
.tuo pils ll’I ro hcum oot elggiw t’noD“
.ecap eht pu dekcip retto eht neht
”,siht ekil uoy gniees dnA“
.keehc sih tsniaga yot tfos eht gnihsup ,elttil a spih reh delggiw ehS
.deb eht otno depmuls eh dnA
.htrof dna kcab spih reh devom retto eht
,pil sih tib nodnarB
,srexob sih no tops pmad eht gnisaet dna ssendrah nwo s’tibbar eht ta gniporg ,deunitnoc ehs ”,noitnem ot toN“
”?taht htiw rehto hcae pleh nac ew ebyaM
.moordeb eht ni edutitta demuserp rieht dna skool rieht no gnitnemmoc ,slrig dna syug gnieye htob
.tfahs sih gnola retsaf dna retsaf devom wap siH
.daeherof sih dessik ehS
.tneitap eb tsuJ" .dekniw ehS ".esimorp
.ni keep a kaens dna yrt ot thgir eht ot denael tibbar ehT
”?dnim ni evah evol ym seod tahw“
,pil rewol sih gnitiB
,moorhtab eht otni kcab deklaw dna
.nodnarB ,semitemos eb nac uoy yknik woh tegrof I"
.gnirewoprevo ton tub gnortS
eht tsniaga kcab mih dehsup retto ehT
.deb eht no eod eht ta delims dna
tfahs reh gnola desaet eh ,htrof dna kcaB
”.syot ruoy htiw gniyalp neeb evah uoY .ym ,yM“
”.tuo uoy pleh dluoc I thguoht I ,kcoc detnaw uoy dias uoY“
.meht dniheb namow a fo tnecs eht thguac eh sa
”.hturt eht uoy llet ot ,detcepxe I naht eroM“
.won elbaliava ,ygolohtna
,niaga dna niaga ,htrof dna kcaB
.esimorp I .ereht thgir eb ll'I
deb eht tsniaga nwod sgel s’nodnarB tes retto ehT
.ni dils pit eht ,troffe elttil yrev htiw dnA .hsup evitatnet
.ti od yllautca thgim
.resolc mih dehsup
.seenk sih ot llef eh
,niaga pal s’nodnarB ni tas dna pu doots ehs sA
.modnaf eht ni seigolohtna rehto fo rebmun a dna ,taeH
.dnopser t’ndid retto ehT
”,aedi rehtona evah I“
,keehc reh gnippuc ,deilper eod eht ”,lleW“
reh ot resolc detoocs eH
.rehtegot skcoc rieht gnisserp ,drawrof denael retto ehT
.oot ,ynneJ knaht tuB“
.eerf dils yot eht ,elttil yb elttil
,edniM JT yb ”sgnileeF dessiM“
.elkcuhc a htiw detfil sredluohs siH ".kciht rO
.moor eht tfel ehs sa
.dnuora denrut naedeaN
”.ydaer er’uoy erus ekam attoG“
.ylrig ton tub ,eninimeF
naedeaN ".emoh esroh taht ekat ot ekil d'uoy kniht I
”.eaN ,taht od ot syaw wef a htiw pu emoc nac ew kniht I“ .delims ynneJ
.rae sih thguac citsale fo pans eht dna seltsur deirruh fo sdnuos ehT
.pu tfahs eht fo flah tnorf eht dekcils ehs ,wap reh otni ebul fo spmup owt rehtona retfA
.dias eh ”,gniticxe s’tI“
.tfahs eht woleb saw demussa eh kcas eht rof gniporg ,drawrof wap a dehcaer eh ,delims eh sA
.denaom tibbar eht ”,ris seY“
srexob sih fo citsale eht rednu stigid sih dekooh nodnarB
,htaerb txen sih htiW
.rethgirb denetsilg erp fo tops eht dna
"?mih ekat dluoc uoy kniht uoY"
.sgel reh neewteb eglub sih gnibbur
.mih fo tnorf ni ti denoitisop dna
ni tibbar eht fo shtaerb tfos eht raeh dluoc retto ehT
devom wap sih dna kcab delims tibbar ehT
.ydaer m’I wonk uoY“
.weiv eht ot erom hcum taht dedda srexob eht fo ylf eht hguorht gnimoc tfahs eht dna
.erofeb hsinif ot elba t’nsaw I“
"?naem uoy od revetahW"
”.tsael eht yas oT“
,pal sih ni delggiw ehS
.retto eht ta yltnatcepxe pu dekool dna tfahs eht dekorts eH
pu kcab doots ehS
.niaga emaceb stnecs eht regnorts eht
.tnorf eht ni eloh a hguorht tuo gnippop kcoc esroh diccalf a htiw
.llah eht nwod rood desolc a no dekconk ehs
.reh morf swap sih gnidils ,niaga daeh reh koohs
".won thgir ta gniyalp er'ew tahw ton s'taht tub
”,flesmih deyojne eh ekil sdnuoS“
.delims eh dna srae sih evoba detser smra siH
# .rood eht desolc dna moorhtab eht ot ffo kcuns naedeaN
.toh llits saw ti tub ,retto na ot dehcatta s’esroh a gniees ddo dekool tI
.kcab elims tub pleh t’ndluoc ehS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.deddon naedeaN ”?eltneg eb tsuJ“
.srae sih otni delwarc hsulb a dna
.elzzum sih ssorca elims deifsitas a htiw revo dellor eh ,htaerb a retfA
"?em rof rood taht denepo uoy dnA"
.hgiht reh tsniaga detser ti sa htgnel reh gnola elzzum sih nar eh
.regnif desiar a htiw ffo mih tuc ehs tub ,eugra ot deirt eh "-eaN tuB"
.kool t'nod tub ,eaN ,nrut yM"
,wap sih morf puc s’tibbar eht gnikaT ”.eruS“
,drow rehtona tuohtiw dnA ".tneitap
,ylleb dna tsehc sih no seno eht nwod ,redluohs sih no sehctolps etihw eht morf stigid reh decnad ehs
.yug a htiw gnipeels ot txen rof ksa dluoc eh tsesolc eht saw tI
.revol reh ta derats dna nwod dial naedeaN
.em tuoba yrrow t’noD“
elkcuhc saw od dluoc nodnarB llA
.trihs reh fo kcab eht rednu swap sih edils ot nageb dna
.detcerroc ehs ”,naeD“
seitnap eht saw ti ,daetsni
.edud a ekil kool t’nod uoY
.enoyna tsuj htiw ti evah t’now eh dna ,mih rof gniht tnatropmi na si xeS“ .deggurhs naedeaN
.ereht oot si tsehc ruoY
ydob sih tsniaga dna
tsrif eht evag ehs nehw rehtruf xaler tub pleh t’ndluoc eH
”.ybab ,uoy evoL .llew peelS“
langis a sa pirg etanoissap sih daersim retto ehT
”?dekrow ssenrah eht tuB“
.delims retto ehT .deksa ynneJ
.nirg deredliweb a htiw deksa nodnarB ”?taht s’tahW“
.koob reh nwod gnittup ,dias eod eht
”,won yeH“ .erom gnitnaw
,kciht a saw ylf eht morf gnidurtorP
.tfahs tneps sih dnuora wap sih htiw llits dna
”.noitnetta erom stnaw eh
,llam eht dnuora dekool eH ".enif ,eniF"
.tsetorp ni kaeuqs deb eht ekam dna
”.od I ekil sevol enoyreve toN“
”?uoy lliw ,lla ti ekat em ekam t’now uoY“
.elihw eht lla gnihsulb dna gnimriuqs ,dekool eH
.mih edisni nottub mrif taht tsniaga desserp dna
.tca eht gnitaeper
.hcti eht gnihctarcs neeb t’ndah nrop dna ,sraey ni nees t’ndah eh weiv a saw tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ssik erom eno mih evag ehs
dias eh sa did retto ehT
”.ti tnaw uoy wonk uoY .nodnarB ,no
stigid reh tuo dellup ehS
naedeaN .spih reh no swap sih tes dna pu tas eH
.shgual eht steg yllaer dna
spih reh htiw hsup lluf tsrif eht evag ehs ,dnopser dluoc nodnarB erofeB
.moorhtab eht ot ffo deklaw dna
.mih ot pu deklaw ehs sa dekwag nodnarB
.sdrow sih revo dellum ehs sa nihc reh ot wap reh tes naedeaN ”.hguoht
.tuo gnippets ,dias ehs ”,puY“
,gnir thgit sih ot eugnot reh gnihsuP
”?won rof deb otni uoy kcut I t’nod yhW
.mih dedlocs naedeaN
.ecnartne s’nodnarB tsniaga wap reh dils retto eht
eugnot sih tsniaga enocilis ehT
mih rednu swap reh decnad ehS
.evitcartta erom hcum os saw rennam lauxes ylticilpxe na hcus ni eglub a gniees tuB
,pit eht ot skcil wef a htiw ,nehT
”.uoy pleh em tel os ,kcoc rof gnimriuqs neeb ev’uoy dias ohw eno eht er’uoY
.yddub ,tiaw attog ew sseuG"
.smra kciht dna tsehc daorb a htiw ,kcub tniop neves a ot deddon ehs
”.mih emalb etiuq t’nac I ,tuB“
dneirfyob reh ta derats yltnelis
.thgim uoy thguoht I“
.klat lla s'ti tuB
– spih s’retto eht emit hcae dnA
”.no esoht evaeL .on ,oN“
,tnemom rehtona rof derats tibbar ehT
.snalp rehto evah I .ha hA"
,mih fo tnorf ni gnidnatS
”.eaN ,krow lliw ti llew woh erus ton m’I ,tpmetta eht etaicerppa I elihW“
.htgnel eht gnola gnissik ,desolc seye
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,edniM JT yb
.mih ni degdol llits yot eht htiw sih tsniaga spih reh detser ehs
,reh ediseb gel sih tes dna
swap reh ni skeehc s'tibbar eht deppuc naedeaN
.tnurg a htiw pil rewol reh tib naedeaN
.htolchsaw pmad a htiw ,srexob eht morf tuo gnikop odlid eht htiw dna dehtolc llits
.ruf sih tsniaga cirbaf eht gnippans ylthgil
”.yrd ti edir ll’I ,noos pu gniht taht ebul t’nod uoy fI“
dehctiwt eson siH ".taht
;eye sih werd tahw t’nsi tsehc reh tuB
.nihc sih gnissik ,derewsna ehs
,enilucsam os dekool mrof reH
,dnik ni spih reh devom ehs wap reh fo tsurht hcae htiW
”.ybab ,erusaelp yM“
,spih sih morf meht deppils dna
"?su dniheb knuks eht tuoba woH
,knird reh dniheb deksa retto eht "?reh
"?woh 'em fo erac ekaT'"
”?siht morf hcum gnitteg uoy erA
.rewohs kciuq a tnaw I kniht I“
.yllacitahpme deddon eH ”.ma I ,hO“
”?ereht ni yako gnihtyrevE“
.keehc sih dekorts ehS
.derednow eh erom eht
.gib oot neeb syawla evah sesroH .haN"
.trihs sih fo meh eht dehcaer ehs litnu
.neeuq ezis a erew uoy kniht d'I ,retteb yna wonk t'ndid I fI"
.aedi siht dah uoy taht evol I
,niaga nepo rood eht draeh eh nehW
.tsehc reh revo smra reh dessorc ehS
”.desserdrevo mees uoy won tuB“
,yawa klaw ot nageb ehs nehW
,llew swonk ehs elpoep wef eht htiw sekoj dwel skcarc ehS .emit eht lla rettug eht ni si dnim reh dnA“
,sredluohs sih revo smra reh depard naedeaN
.em tuoba yrrow t’noD“
.dnuora dekool ehS ".nodnarB
,raey evif tsal eht retfA"
”?yako ,pu denaelc uoy teg nac ew os tuo llup annog m’I .ereh yats uoY“
.tceffe eht ot dedda sgel reh neewteb eglub eht dnA
.reh ot teef sih dereffo neht
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.hgis a htiw srexob sih ni eglub eht dna nwod dekool nodnarB
",rehtie ecneirepxe dlrow-laer hcum evah t'ndid uoy ,uoy tem I erofeb naem I"
-- naedeaN fo sthguoht ot derednaw dnim siH
”sfeiraeB ro srexoF“
”.worromot noitnetta erom siht evig ot deen I tub ,rewohs eht ni taht naelc ot elba saw I“
.noitidda taerg a saw sihT“
.sthgin emos gniyot uoy draeh ev'I tuB"
.mih ot resolc ni denael retto eht
.resserd eht ot devom dna deddon naedeaN
.moordeb eht ot siht ekat s'teL"
”?uoy erew erehw ,woN“
.yaw emas eht hcti taht hctarcs lliw ti fi wonk t’nod
.flesreh gniporg ,dias ehs
.nwod meht dils neht
.snaej reh tsniaga enohp reh fo eniltuo eht htiw deyalp dna
,no denrut llits saw eh taht hguone railimaf saw tI
.taht fo enon" ,yllufyalp dedlocs ehs ",won yeH"
,ecalp ni meht gniruces ,thgir sih neht ,gel tfel sih rednu mraerof reh dekooh ehs ,kcab edils txen eht nO ”.erusaelp htiW“
”?hcti taht hctarcs ot hguone dooG“
.kcab mih dehsup naedeaN
,drawrof tsurht kcen dna elzzum reh elihw nwod dna pu devom sdap wap reH
,spih reh llor ot deunitnoc retto eht
.ylsuoenatlumis saera htob gnitalumits
.kool lacizziuq a evag eh
”.em tog uoy drah woh ta kool ,naem I“
,evom tfiws eno htiw dnA
.enecs eht ni tsol saw tibbar eht reh dlot eman reh dias eh yaw eht dna enot gnidaelp siH
.hguorht tfahs eht dehsup retto eht
”.oot ,em rof no-nrut a si siht ekil uoy gniees noitnem ot toN“
.mih otni dils yot eht fo driht a dna
.rewohs a tuohtiw dluoc ehs sa tseb sa dneirfyob reh pu gninaelc emit reh koot ehS
.neercs reh ta yawa deppat ehs ,llitS
,owt msaps mih gnihctaw
”,tnaw uoy sa hcum sa ylnO“
.hguorht enohs ygrene fo tnuoma llams a dna denepo seye s’nodnarB
.evol edam dna etamitni erew yeht yaw eht fo
.deilper tibbar eht
.koot ehs pets hcae htiw decnuob taht tfahs tcere
.nrob saw ehs yad eht sa dekan ,eod eht ot pu delwarc dna
naeD“ .erusaelp ni
.srexob sih ta gnippots
nirg gnisaet a ni htuom sih fo renroc eht pu devruc tibbar ehT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.resserd eht fo pot no elttob ssalg llams a tes ehS
.teg dluoc ehs sa mih otni peed sa gnisserp
.deksa naedeaN ”?ti ekil uoY“
.mih ta delims ehS
.stnap thgit ni ,tif dna llat
– ecalp ni detfihs tibbar ehT
reh dnuora smra sih depparw eH ".syawla
”.elggiw ot moor ssel
”.su fo rehtie truh annaw t’noD
.smra sih dessorc nodnarB
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
evah d’I ,ni erom saw ereht fi ebyam ,lleW“
”?yako ,em rof snalp rehto tog ev’I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.esuoh eht dnuora semitemos ,deb ot semitemos – erofeb sehtolc sih nrow d’ehs ,eruS
.raeg rehto rieht htiw ecalp sti ni kcab tfahs esroh eht tes ehS
.yug a rof ssap tsomla dluoc ehs
.sreh fo edis eht tsniaga daeh sih desserp nodnarB
.emoclew er’uoY“
,kcab s’retto eht fo selcsum eht gnola tsriF
.guh a ni retto eht depparw dna
.ylderit deksa tibbar eht ”?ffo teg uoy diD
.spih reh gnikcor nageb neht
.ylisae mih otni knas tigid tsrif ehT
,delttes saw gnihtyreve retfA
trihs-t yarg sih ni ereht doots naedeaN
".pu dekrow em gnitteg adniK ?erus uoY"
.dedaelp tibbar eht
.stigid sih rednu deslup kcoc s’nodnarB
.erom flesmih dekorts eh dna
.hcum uoy raeh t’ndid I tub ,esion fo not a edam I wenk I“
;llef waj sih dnA .pu tas eh
,ylleb dna tsehc s’tibbar eht gnola swap reh dils ehs sa ruf etihw-dna-kcalb sih ni sliart gnitaerc
dnuora denrut ehs ”,yrrow t’noD“
”?yako ,uoy fo erac ekat em teL
,ylwols ,dna niaga deddon tibbar detsuahxe eht ,daeh sih gnivom ylnO
.delggig ehS ”.syaw tnereffid wef a ni nuf eb nac siht ,sediseB“
kcab tibbar eht kcor ot ecrof hguone htiw drawrof ti demmals neht
.mih ta gnidnuop tpek dna elttil a sgel reh daerps ehS
.kcab sih no ruf eht hguorht swalc trohs reh nar naedeaN
.rehto eht revo hgiht eno gnitfihs ,ecalp ni delggiw eh sa
.taht wonk I ,traehteews ,hO"
.niaga mih dessik dna
,niaga thguoht eh ,siht tuB
”.hsinif t’ndid I tuB .esolc dna pu dekrow tog ylniatrec I .oN“
naom eurt a tuo tel eh ,sgel sih neewteb noitalumits eht htiw denibmoc snoitasnes eht dna
”.taht htiw uoy pleh em teL“
.skeehc sih neewteb elzzum reh desserp dna seenk reh ot devom ehS
,sedis s'nodnarB nwod delevart swap s'retto ehT