emoh gninruter nopu kcab etirw I taht detseuqer uoY
.siht sa hcus nwad a morf gnidih on si erehT
.ecalp fo tuo saw ti taht hcuot a yrrow I tub
?gnihcaorppa yps I nwad eht neht taht si ,hhhA
.neht ,noitseuq ym derewsna ev’uoY
,ereh revolc fo ebolg neddih a ,ezag lamron eht ssim thgim
oga syad xis dna keew eno gniteem tsal ruo gninrecnoc etirw I ,uoy esaelp ti fI ,riS
!mih nihtiw sdrow ynam os dah xof eht taht wenk ohW !ssendoog yM
:drow erom eno ylno htiw uoy evael I
,seitivitsef s’gnineve eht rof
!niaga noitseuq eht egdod ton od dna
,ereh egap eht ssorca enil eht ward tsum I ,salA
:thgis suoiruc tsom a yb deteerg saw I ereht tey dnA
.thginot detrohs leef neve yam stnavres eht raef I dna
,rehto hcae htiw emit ni evom ot nageb
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY ”.xoF“ sa
— eton uoy-knaht a fo esiug eht ekat tsum sihT
reverof niamer tnecs emos hguoht         ,tsud dna
?ainixolg eht ot noitnetta ruoy ward daetsni I yaM
.swen eht fo deklat ew ,yad eht fo deklat ew
?remraw eht lla moor eht peek tey
.seye tseroop eht neve htiw esoht yb daer eb dna ediw nepo flesti yal yam siht sa teiuq os koob a taht ralugnis ti dnif I
,I taht rehtegot gnineve eht rof em gniknaht fo boj tneuqole na hcus enod evah uoY
naem dluoc esormirP a elihw ,regnad fo gninraw a eb thgim nordnedodohR A
,todeloT ,tsetal reh htiw ,skoob lareves fo rohtua eht s’ehS
,enon yb dessaprus si ytuaeb esohw xof a oT
,emoh elbatrofmoc a ni efil ym dneps I hguohT .yoj erar a
.reh fo retteb eht steg netfo ainamohparg esohw
.flesmih nataS yb htraE siht no ecalp ni tup nis eht htiw yot ew dna ,deppetsrevo
.evoL delaecnoC" naem dluow trowrehtoM dna
nosrep ruoy no ylesolc oot gnihcaorcne yb trofmocsid dna niap desuac evah snoitca ym tahT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,etoyoc raed ,uoy dluoW
teop roop a htiw noonretfa eerferac a dneps ot poots dluow flesruoy sa hcus rettirc eltneg dna suoip a taht
,god.ecioveht ta
gnicnartne tfig yht nahT laem retaerg on pus llahs I
!eye eht ot gnisaelp dnif ew taht sgniht eht si ti gnillet woH
.uoy tuohtiw evil ylurt
?htfif eht yadirF no
,thgiled a ylurt saw yad taht nedrag eht ni uoy htiw gniklaW
.noitats wol ym fo esuaceb ylpmis noitcaretni fo egaugnal eht ni deloohcsnu ma I taht kniht t’noD
,nedrag nwo ruoy nihtiw klaw ehT
,xof lufthgiled yM  xoF
;sainedrag eht tuoba deksa uoy ,noitidda nI
,daersim spahrep dah I taht deirrow
.erom ecno rotisiv a fo ecneserp eht gnitseuqer erofeb dessap evah ot emit fo tnuoma etairporppa na si siht taht thguat neeb ev’I dna
"ytiruP" rof doots seilil etihW
!nettims flesym llac ot etatiseh ton od I
nedrag eht ni gnol os gniyllad yb tnemssarrabme rehtaf ym esuac ylraen dluow I
sah rennid tneuqesbus a dna nedrag a ni stnalp fo noissucsid a taht noitnetta ym ot emoc sah tI
,thgirb eht rof eye na ev’uoy wonk I
,rettal eht eb llahs ti raef I
.desaelp os eb dluow I taht kniht ton od I
,ylwols revewoh ,srehtiw dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.dnah ta mossolb eht ees ot mih ediseb yllufecargnu tsom dettauqs neht
spahrep ,syas trowrehtom sA
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,gniwohs roop a nevig ev’tsum esnopser gniremmats ym :I saw os dnA
.wonk ton od I erus m’I
,ainixolg eht noitnem uoY
.sdrow rof ssol a ta ylraen flesym dnif ,ecno rof
!sderdnuH !sessik fo sneT !elbert dna elbuod uoy ot pu
.rolocsid dna nworb nrut ot mossolb eht fo etihw tfos eht sesuac rewolf ainedrag eht no retaw hcum oot ,wonk llew uoy erus m’I sa ,roF
fi tseb eb dluow tI
,nialp erom erew ti fi
,raelc snoitnetni ym gnikam ni llew did I taht wonk I
,uoy ot srettel gnitirw pu ton dna deb ot gniog eb ot
.snoitcartta dna snoitceffa terces fo stnih rieht
?ecneserp ruoy htiw su sselb uoy lliW
.:llew sa ,lufituaeb srewolf hcus kniht I taht yas ot etatiseh ton lliw I
.sruoy flesmih redisnoc dluow ohw xof A .ton erac I
.nedrag s’eno fo yteritne eht ypucco ot hcum oot spahrep tub
,emoc ot yad thgirb a fo espmilg a edivorp syawla uoy lliw
.esle lla evoba klaw a gniyojne ,saw I ereht tey dnA !skooB
,didnelps etiuq eb ot meht dnuof I
!reicnaf rewolf dna
.ereht lezah hctiw fo mossolb etal a fo gnikeep yhs eht
,deilper I dna riah s’nediam eht tuoba deksa uoY
deniatretne ,ruoh eht yb yawa gnippils fleS ym fo eganioc eht leef I
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”sevissiM“ saw sihT      .L .C
redisnoc ot — gnineve na hcus dneps oT
,noitaredisnoc rehtruf nO
gnihton ot dedaf sit‘ litnu         ruoh eht yb
,diviv ylgnikirts os
taht timda tsum I
.srewolf fo egaugnal eht wonk ,oot ,I roF
,hA .ssenesolc dnuofwen siht ni etacorpicer yllufeelg sa
,enituor eht fo derob saw I
…erom neeb dah ereht taht dluow ,hA
,etoyoc raeD  -C .llet oD
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb dna ,flesreh rohtua eht yb daer
.detaluclac tub ,lausac ton si hcuot taht I sa llew sa wonk uoY
.noinapmoc ruoy fo sdrow gnirednaw eht dnim ton od uoy taht epoh I
,emoc ot sessik fo maerd yam flesruoy sa hcus eno taht wonk oT
”tuo uoy hctac“ sa hcum os t’ndid I
.koot ti lla si ecnedifnoc fo esimorp a dna ,repap emos ,nep A
.derongi eb ot thguan saw
,ees ot regae si hcihw em fo trap llams on si erehT
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
!tfig a hcus eviecer ohw meht ot gnisselb a sit‘ detbuodnU
.nosaer ralimis rof nedrag taht ni ereht pu dnuow htob dah ew taht kniht I .won od I
.gnilaets htrow eb yaM gnirahs htrow tnemom yr’vE
.swodahs gnitsac nigeb dna ssenkrad eht hcaerb uoy ssenneddus gnisirprus a htiw neht dna ,tsrif ta ylluferac
?htflewt eht no rennid rof su nioj yam uoy spahrep tub ,raef I ,htfif eht rof etal oot si tI
,slauqe neewteb ssendnik dna tsurt fo pihsnoitaler a dliub ot ylno tnetni ym saw tI .noitcafsitassid ro thgils yna rof ygolopa lanoitidnocnu dna etaidemmi ym reffo tsum I
!dnah ta eussi eht sserdda ton od ylniatrec yeht ,revewoH
.ecneirepxe elohw eht fo tuo tfel leef dluohs I kniht I
.dessim ton erew ruf ot sregnif
.yromem ym ni ylmrif tsom kcits lliw tahw si taht llew
,dlot m’I ,eno ton rof
taht thgis tsrif ta evol siht leef ylurt od uoy taht eb ti dluoC !deedni ainixolG
.sterger ym gnoma feihc si dna
,xofnogard reppad eht ,nelarD yb dna
,elpmaxe lacitcarp erom a roF ".evoL
.kcab etirw uoy taht epoh od I tub
?nwohs dna d’ppilc sesor ton era tey
lla ti fo rennam gnilfits eht epacse ot epoh ylecracs dluoc I
.nwo sih uoy llac dluow ohw etoyoc A .”niaga“
?emit ruoy htrow saw taht em ni was uoy taht ,neht ,ti si tahW
,yawa neddih ti erew ,tuhs ti erew dnA
.ssik taht sserdda tsum I
,etsah ni traped ot dah I taht saw ti suhT
,rehtaf ym ro em naht erom eta ylniatrec uoy rof
.nrom eht ,neht ,yaleD ,uoy htiw ti ereW
.sreksihw eht nopu ssik a ro
,tneserp spahrep I naht nosrep reyhs a flesym ssefnoc I
.ssik llams rehtona tey fo erised eht rof senil roop ym gnilbbircs esaec ot elbanu
,xof raed yM  .rJ ,.V .V
.rohcna ta
,erom ecno oS .niaga rof gnol
,tniartser ym fo ecnedive nI
,si ti htflewt ehT
.nedrag sih fo stniop renif eht gnissucsid ruoh yppah a tneps ew nierehw
.sdnuob ym deppetsrevo evah thgim I taht
!etoyoc raed ,taht ssim I tub
.dnob terces a fo tnalp eht
,mets eht sselb deedni yam     gnimoolb won ,elgnis ,esor A
,skeew owt neeb sah tI
?yas uoy ,rennid A .sruoy ot woN
?ssenkrad fo egde eht no revoh reverof uoy lliw ro
.desluper erew uoy elihw
,llew sa ti was uoy taht tsurt I
,dneirf ym ,noonretfa tnasaelp a dedivorp lla sihT
ynam os retfa drow elpmis taht dna
.tser eht naht rewol dehcuorc eb ti hguoht ,lufituaeb etiuq ti kniht I
.etuca ylralugnis eb tsum ezag s’xof a os
.won thgir uoy knaht ot naht erom gnihton tnaw I !si ti dna
,ecnedifnoc ni sruoY
”sevissiM“   yojne esaelP
.yteirporpmi ot del
dna galf ot htraeh eht ni erif eht esuac tey dna esaec reven lliw taht gninip dna sgnignoL
hguoht ,tsaob fo tuo ton siht yas I
.hguoht ,flesym detcartsid ev’I
.nihtiw srewolf fo tfig lanif eht dna rettel ruoy fo gninaem eht llew ekat I .tsum eht tsdima
.erutseg eht nruter em tel traeh ym ni yrevarb on dna
nrut ni niap taerg em sesuac
,kniht I ,erew erehT
.ti slliw ylimaf ym sa
,emas eht lla derettalf flesym timda tsum I ,revewoH
,wap ot wap ,woble ot woble fo sehsurb lausac esoht dna
,os yas ot pu thgil srae ym sekam ti
,serised ruoy etas nedrag ruo morf sgnittuc esormirp dna trowrehtom
,uoy nihtiw kaerb ot yad emos lliW
,srewolf fo deklat eW
.emit eht ta tuo ti tniop ot ecnahc eht t’ndah I hguoht
— etoyoc tahT
,ylpmis dias dna enim pota dnah ruoy dial uoy nehw
.uoy no noitcelfer a yaw on ni saw gnitrap ytsah ym dna ,em erofeb levart hcum dah I dna
.srae nwo sih htiw meht raeh niaga ecno yam eh
!ti rof doog si tahw fo hcum oot yb deliops eb rewolf eht sa noitaerc s’doG fo noitcefrep hcus nevE
llahs dna ,tpecca ylbmuh I
– nekciuq yam traeh eht ’ohT
– pal yam eugnot eht ’ohT
I tahw si tahT .ylpeed os em dehcuot taht
,nedrag eht hguorht llorts ruo gnirud esrev etirovaf ruoy fo yna etouq ot denilced uoy hguohT
!owt ni gnikaerb traeh ym tlef I ,retfa lufhsab os ,evom ot yhs os erew uoY !ssik ehT
.dnah ta gnieb naht rehtar
,nref gniwolf taht ,riah s’nediam fo klat ruoY
”sevissiM“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
deed rehtruf yna fo ecalp ni dnats sdrow roop ym tel tub
.stnalp hcus rehto ynam
.etulosba si ecnedifnoc eht
,xof raed ,em htiw efas yats syawla llahs sdrow ruoY
,tnemevom fo dna noitom fo egaugnal eht fo osla wonk I
rehtegot nees eb ew tsal eht eb taht yam dna
,ylwols hcaorppa uoy ,revewoh ,nwad eht htiw sA
.skoob yb yb dednuorrus
tonnac I ,esormirp eht sA
,ezag ruoy fo ssenneek eht gniwonK
.elbayojne os rehtegot emit ruo dnuof I hguoht
,evitca dnim ruoy peek ot ereht skoob hguone ton
.gnittes a hcus ni noitasrevnoc ruo eunitnoc ot gniksa ni drawrof oot saw I taht deraef dah I rof ,yadot rettel ruoy htiw deteerg eb ot dethgiled dna desirprus saw I
– hsiwsa dna gnitnaP
ma I dna tfel tsuj evah uoy sa ,ylitsah etirw I
,sruoY .suoiruc niamer I ,sthguoht ruoy htiw kcab em etirw od esaelP
— uoy ni tnenamrep dna largetni si taht gnihtemos saw ti fi gnirednow flesym hctac I
,ecneh syad ruof ecneserp ruoy htiw su sselb ot sa dnik os eb
hguoht ,hgual ton dluoc I ,denetsahC
.nref riah s’nediam elpmis eht ni devlovni ytuaeb fo gniht a si ereht taht dnuof evah I
,xoF  xoF ,ylerecniS
,nedrag taht ni dellips neeb dah ynam os retfa emosenol ,drow taht dnA
saw laem eht retfa dna erofeb htob
.srewolf eht tcepsni ot tlenk dna enac detceffa sih nwod dial dah etoyoc a
.emit eht ta sdrow ruoy no pu kcip ton did I taht kniht ton od tub
.niaga rehtegot nees eb ot ton erew ew
.tirips emas eht ni uoy ot etirw llahs I ,sdrow nwo ym fo ytiruces eht eetnaraug tonnac I hguohtla dna
.em ni derednegne thgin taht gnignol eht rof esrev fo enil a etirw ot elba eb ylecracs llahs I
.ti dneps deedni od I
,nwad eht otnu edecer thgin dna gnol ere moolb yam r’wolf eht ’ohT
,ecnaraeppa rieht yb kcaba nekat yllaitini saw I hguoht
,emit siht gniksa ma ohw I si tI .”emoc“
.deklat ew tey dnA
,hO !sruoh flah a dna owt ylraen tub
etutsa snoitavresbo ruoy dnif I
.delaecnoc eb tseb thguo etoyoc a rof evol s’xof eno
.em detnorfnoc eh nehw deltsirb liat s’rehtaf ym yaw eht
yb ecalp ni ylmrif era taht seiradnuob ehT
.ytrap taht ta eb ot detnaw su fo rehtieN
.sdrow htiw neek dna ,daer llew htob rehtaf ruoy dna uoy dnuof I
.ylimaf ruoy dna uoy ot od yam I taht
,dnim ruoy dna ynapmoc ruoy htob erahs ot
yregdurd eht morf em deucser — noinapmoc lufthgiled taht
.ytisnetni dna euh rieht yb kcaba nekat saw I taht
,ronam s’-G retsiM ta
.tegrof noos lliw I taht gniht a ton saw ,sdnuorg didnelps ruoy dnuora
,ytterp ti dnuof I taht
nehw emit a rof nraey gnieb yrev s’xof roop a ekam yeht
.rehto hcae htiw emit rehtruf dneps ot ecnahc eht evah lliw ew taht epoh od I
.su niatsus yeht lliw oot os ,feirb eb sdrow ruo hguohtlA
.nosrep a sa uoy fo noitamitse ym htiw enil ni dna
?noitativni ym ot uoy yas tahW
.kni.oykam no
straeh gninraey sdraw’t straeh sA ylisae sa desrevart eb ecnatsid taht dluoW
,sdrow a htiw nurrevo eb llahs I spahrep ,rO
ylidaets spets ruO
,lufrednow deedni saw doof ehT
,ssendnof tsomtu eht htiW
!uoy knaht niaga dna ,uoy knaht ,uoy knahT
,dnim sih no hcum sdnif etoyoc A
,nwonk ecneserp ym ekam ot ylision dna ylwols dehcaorppa I
,elbatalap doof eht dnuof uoy taht tsurt I
ti ekam llahs I ,rehto hcae ees ew txen ehT
,yb dessap dah ohw yna yb nees eb ot mossolb fo epyt eht saw ti taht eveileb t’nod I
.niaga luos tnatneper siht morf raeh ton llahs uoy ,tseuqer ruoy yb tuB
,tca eht retfa dnim ym nihtiw gnitallegalf-fles flesym dnuof I dna
.erutuf eht rof em niatsus lliw tahw si taht
,etsah fo tuo
!tey mih nihtiw yad emos sah seod xof raed ruo spahreP
taht sgnihT .ssentfos rof eye na hcus evah uoY
.dloheb ot thgis eht etiuq era hcus taht kniht oot I dna
saw yad taht nedrag eht ni uoy htiw klaw oT
.rehtegot srewolf fo seutriv eht gnitnuocer emit emos dneps yam ew taht ,aet erofeb em tcepxe od esaelp
.gniddib ruoy ta ”emoc“
.redro ni era seigolopa dnasuoht a ,taht roF
,elims taht ,hcuot taht si ti tub
ylraelc tsom rebmemer tub pleh tonnac I
,ecnedifnoc fo kaeps uoY ,etoyoC  .etoyoc A
.egaugnal ylno eht yldrah era sdroW
.efil fo dna drow eht fo srevol
.nrut ni kcab meht ydnab ot elba eb dnim reven
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoY .fles-tsop/mf.rohcna
”.uoy tuohtiw evil tonnac I“
,ecarg sti htiw eltnam yht snroda hcihw r’wolf eht si edamnu won teY
.ynapmoc lufthgiled eht ot nosirapmoc ni delap tub
,snoisulla hcus no pu kcip ot wonk neve thgim flesruoy sa hcus eno taht gnitanicsaf ti dnif I
secalp ruo ot yawa dellac erew ew sa
,gninrom eht erofeb thgin fo htaerb dloc tsal taht was I ,uoy nI
.ssenesolc derebmemer eht ot tsol saw peels fo ruoh na ynam dna
,thgin a nwad yr’ve dnA tnemeuoned a hcaorppa xamilc yr’ve hguohT
.thgiled a naht erom
.naw eht nopu tliops eb tey dna dnof worg ecarbme s’evol yam tey os
”,C“ sa ,rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
,gniht suoutlumut a si eriseD
.nedrag ylevol s’-G hguorht llorts a yb
neeb evah wal s’doG dna yteicos
,etoyoc tseraed yM  -C
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
tsacdop a rof daer gnieb fo ssecorp eht ni yltnerruc
htiw flesym dnif I dna
,noitirtnoc tserecnis htiW
,dlohesuoh eht fo xof demeetse eht ot ylpeR  .rJ ,.V .V
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,ytterp naht erom era sdrow ruoY
.snoitseuq derewsnanu
.eton su yap ohw srotisiv wef tnacs eht dna stnadnetta s’rehtaf ym yb ylno
.sainedrag dna riah s’nediam eht pu gnirb I nehw yltcerroc snoitnetni ym enivid uoY
,nruter ni ylper on tcepxe lliw I
:yas I ,taht gniwonK
,nedrag eht ni rehtegot tneps ew taht yad taht nO
.ysub swap ruoy peek ot snep on
,seitud ruo fo eerf erew ew emit eht yb ,revewoh ,etal nworg dah ruoh ehT
.tsej I taht ,esruoc fo ,wonk uoY
?smaerd fo gnihtemos yltcirts eb snoitceffa ruo lliw ro
.ralucatceps gnihtemos fo esimorp eht
– egatnavdasid a ta em dnif uoY
htob fo tfig lanif siht yaM
,dediced evah I ,mets ehT
.hcus ni deloohcs eb ton noitats ym fo eno taht enigami ton od rof
.gninesool ni emit gnol a eb dluow eugnot ruoy taht llet dluoc I tub
swap fo hcuot a erahs ot
.enim ni wap a tuohtiw tfel ma ,oot ,I taht tcaf eht fo tuo tub
uoy htiw sdnuorg eht klaw ot dna
ni gnikcal dnif I taht ssentfos a ebircsed sevael eht dna ,cra etaciled tsom a secart
thgiled a hcus saw tI
?tuoba klat ynam os
.snoicipsus gnisuora morf peek ot ma I fi
:nruter ni gnihtemos gnidivorp yb rewsna ruoy tuo esaet I taht riaf ylno si tI
— erom hcus ynam gnidneps
,ha…hcum os hsulb htob dluoc ew taht wonk oT
,rediw eht nepo erew ti fI
,traeh ym nihtiw kaew gnihtemos si ti spahreP .”emoC“
htiw sainedrag fo sdrow ruoY
.esrev teewsrevo rieht htiw steerts eht gnirettil steop nettims sseltnuoc eht gnoma nettogrof eb ot demood ma I taht
.tiaw eht yojne dluow em fo tsom eht tub
:elpmaxe roF .steuquob fo stfig ni delaecnoc segassem dnes dluoc srevol hcihw yb motsuc denoihsaf-dlo na ,srewolf fo egaugnal eht ,elpmaxe rof ,si erehT
.rehtaf ym fo tseheb eht ta etirw I ,ris raeD
,revewoh ,otsug hcus htiw gniyojne enoemos ees ot yppah ma I
.neht ,tsap skeew emos fo klaw nedrag eht no rehtruf kaeps su teL
taht emit eht taht aedi on dah I