.stunaep alluf xobkcol a eveirter dna worceracS degnared yletelpmoc ,demra-ylivaeh a nwod ecaf ot noillim eviF“
,esae htiw klub evissam s’nevaR dereets eh dna—
”.noitats s’niatpaC ruoy ot gninraw eht tneS .ris ,t’ndiD“
”.stunaep ref boj siht ’niod yllaretil er’eW
”!lessev dezirohtuanU“
yrgna fo gnirts gnol a gniweps
.deggurhs yrthguaD ”,yltnerappA“ ”?ti t’nia ,stoidi fo lluf tsuj s’yxalaG“
.deggurhs remmahworC ”,wonk I fi lleH“
.noitarepsaxe ni namsmleh eht no gnidnuor
mleh sdrawot gninrut ,delley remmahworC ”!rettO“  .pleh emos eigroJ teg ot emit ,thgirlA
.draobyek eht ssorca gniylf sregnif ,dnuora denrut neht dna
,knalB .secaf knalB
”,aeagopyh sihcarA“
?rednerrus ot su gnillet peek ti si seod kcuf eht yhW“
”.yrthguaD ,thgir llems t’nod siht tuob‘ gnihtemoS
.niatpaC sih ta gnilims dna pu gninethgiarts ,dias eh ”,siht evol annog rey hO“
!malb-malb-malB !malB
,dehctip dna deredduhs nevaR
”!sdratsaB“  ”.ogniB“ ”.aitiliM“
”?elur lanidrac ym s’tahW !yrthguaD“
,deralg dna deffuh rettO  ”!pihs ym attuolleh yloh raet yeht erofeb sgniht gnikcuf esoht egdod gnikcuf uoy won ,rettO ,egdod dias I“
,derumrum remmahworC ”,mmmH“ ”.noillim eviF“
.desseug eigroJ ”?’nitoohS“ ”?’niod eb uoy dluohs tahW .yltcaxE“  ”’.nihtuN“
pilb thgilrats a ni pu nrub ro enutrof dna emaf ot yaw rieht dnif yeht fi dna
.pu lla siht tes dah ohw toidi eht—
,derettum remmahworC
.nevaR drawot yaw sti gnihtirw
’niwercs yeknom ,doog on ,efil-wol ,ssa paehc ahcnub a tahW .rekcuf rehtoM ?ti dloS“
.ylderit detcerroc ehs
.noitcerid lareneg s’ihccurT ni ylirgna gnilialf dnah eno
”?ereht tuo s’tahW .iccuG ,em ot klaT“  .dereets rehto eht elihw wap elttil eliga eno htiw snottub ta gnippat
,revo dehcaer dna dennirg rettO
.metsys eht yreuQ“
saeS tnatsiD & sratS nettogroF levon gnimocpu eht
,egdirb eht no ecneliS  ”?lla ta gnihtynA
.lluh s’nevaR edistuo ssenkrad eht pu til taht
”,lufrednow gnikcuF .lufrednoW“
namow decaf-tehctah a ot gniddon ,dias yrthguaD ”,yug weN
.ecnats tser edarap a gnimussa neht dna
.ihccurT“ ”?ys-ohW“   ”.ris ,ihccurT“
.eson reh gnola gnirocs ,ti dniheb dewollof rehtona sa drah reh gnihcnup
”!gnimocnI—eb t’ndluohs
”.slive owt fo ressel eht esohc dna htam eht diD
”—t’ndid I ?gninraw tahW !?gninraW“
edur gnihtemos dekwauqs rettO
,delbmuts enoyreve ,stcapmi eroM ”—kcuf eht ohw wonk ew os tog ev’uoy gnihtyna ,atad rosneS
,ffo mih gnittuc ,regnif eno desiar rettO
”!ti-no-ti no-ti nO“ ”!eigroJ“
.namow a fo aedi sih yltcaxe toN
”!rettO ,pu re‘ kcaB“
”.gnitoohs trats dna tegrat gnikcuf a dniF“  .diputs ylenasni
.stegrat rof gnihcraes
,dednamed remmahworC
.edis reh gnola ylirgnuh delwarc taht
,gnimaercs tpek snoxalk eht tub
,deredduhs pihs ehT   ”?—s’tahW
rab eulb dnoces eht sa thgit no dleh dna riahc s’niatpaC sih fo kcab eht ta debbarg remmahworC
.ereht tuo snoiprocS dna sekanS esoht ekil sdnuor amsalp elbatsnu—
.thgir ti nettog dah remmahworC
,sserP dereveS morf 1202 ni esaeler rof eud
.pu s’bmuht a rettO evag remmahworC ”,dog knahT“
,dluow yeht ekil kool t’ndid tI ”.ssim-ssim-ssiM“
haeY“  .swap hsiretto eliga fo serutseg detamina yb deinapmocca—tnangidni ,yrgna—gnirettahc eroM  ”!rettO“
,sedis htob pu devahs daeh
kool gnol a kcuns—
.neercs eht no dleif atad a ta gnippat ,dias yrthguaD
.tey reh rof epoh eb thgiM
.derats dna deknilb remmahworC
,enil-no gnimoc stnemamra
”?taht ssim uoy d’kcuf eht woH
.noitats sih ot kcab rettO gnioohs ,dias yrthguaD
”!nosnegroJ .dnim reveN“ ”—lleW“
,drib eht mih deppilf dna
.emit taht ’ris‘ oN  ”.ti no m’I“
?snoitaluger eht yb gnihtyreve dna hsilop dna tipS“
erehT .yas strahc eht ekil tsuj
.ynam oot erew ereht—
!?erehwyna gniod worceracS a si kcuf eht tahW
sredipS ecnerefsnarT kcohS erew yeht thguoht yeknom gnihsup repap emos ,esac siht ni ,tpecxE
”,em llet t’noD .dog hO“ ”.gniht erom enO“
.yllacitegolopanu deggurhs yrthguaD
.demaercs eh ”!ecarB“ ,nehT
leehw eht debbarg eh neht dna
.eno sees eh nehw ssa a-eceip enif a swonk rettO ?eeS“  .pu sbmuht owt niatpaC sih evag neht dna—
.repmet sih lortnoc ot gnilggurts ,htaerb peed a werd remmahworC
.stnecserc gnilbmut fo
.ylkciuq htuos tnew sgniht—did ylbativeni lla yeht sa—eugor tnew sIA eht nehw oS
”,snoiprocS dna sekanS“
.stunaeP“  .kcab thguorb ti
.tsael eht yas ot lacitpeks saw kool s’yrthguaD ”?yllaeR“
”,hcus emos ro sredipS .tahT
.ssenisub tnatropmi eht ot gninruter ,deksa remmahworC ”?hcum woh ,oS“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.ecaps peed otni ylirgna dehtirw dna
.dnuora gnilrihw ,deppans remmahworC ”!?tahW“ !hguoC
.worceracS siht htiw ereh tuo me‘ kcuts
,deneffits yrthguaD
.ylediw gnilims ,dias remmahworC
.edistuo ssenkrad eht pu gnithgil selissim ygrene eulb thgirb eht ta regnif a gnibbats
.yltnatsni sneris eht gnillik
.esion fo suonohpocac a htiw egdirb eht gnillif
.siht evol annog reY“
sgodhctaw IA ytilibapac detimil erew sworceracS ”.eb t’naC“ .yas
”?’niod ay er’lleh eht tahW !eigroJ“  .edis eno ot noitats yrellitra delabmig a fo ecaps depmarc eht otni deffuts nam fo kcolb dedaeh-dnolb ,gnikluh a—
.gnignir snoxalk eht tes ti duol os eciov A
”.drow laiciffo eht saw tahT .depparcs dna denoissimmoceD“
.dekrab remmahworC ”!eihcooC“  .redrig leets a sa yldduc sa tuoba dekool ihccurT
”.elkcip a siht t’niA .em kcuf lleW“
”!eihcooH ,ecaps ytpme ton si tahT !kcuf-kcuf-kcuF“
.niatpaC ,worceracS“
”?ereht tuo enihcam htaed citohcysp taht fo ssa eht ot depparts pu dne
”!em ot klaT !iccuG .rettO
.snoxalk eht revo draeh eb ot demaercs remmahworC
.ereht tuo worceracS a s’tahT
remmahworC sueannihP
1202 ni esaeler rof eud osla gniK nosmirC
”,boj siht no ’nikat elur lanidrac ym ekorB“
”!ffo smmoc nmaddog eht tuhS“
,yllaer enilediug a fo erom s’tahT“
”.nam dooG .tsefinam ehT
.elpmet sih tsniaga gnippat sregnif
”!ereh attuo su teg tsuJ
,detovip dop delabmig ehT
”,krowrepap eht pu dewercs enoemoS“ ”?won tahw ehT“
?ereh tuo yaw gniod worceracS a si kcuf eht tahW“
,reidlos elttil doog a ekil pu gnicarb ,dekrab ehs ”!riS“
”—lleh eht woH .yrthguaD ,egdirb siht no sthgil gnikcuf dnasuohT
.revo si siht nehw snoxalk lla evomeR“
”!rednerrus-rednerrus-rednerruS“
”?—rey ni kcits taht si gib woh tsuJ .lrig nmaddoG“
.ti fo pot no gnittis s’worceracS
?ti s’tahT .sredipS“
.remmahworC ot seye sih gnidils ,daer eh
.os kniht t’noD“ ”?esle gnihtoN
?gninnacS“ ”!su gninnacs s’tI“
esrevinu gnikcuf elohw eht ni elpmas tnalp tunaep nwonk tsal eht seod woH“
.ffo namsmleh eht gnittuc
ot reh detcepxe d’eh gniht tsal eht saw tahT ”?worceracS“
”—yna elpoep uoy wonk neve t’nod I ekil s’tI !doG
,mrots a pu desruc dna demaercs elpoep elihw pihs eht revo lla gnidnuos snoxalk
,srab eulb gnikans eht dniheb duolc eulb esned eht gninniht fo boj tneced a did dna tohs doog ytterp a saw eH
.mottob eht raen sdrow owt ta
) etaceH dna ,sratS dna kraD ,itegnereS( seires itegnereS eht fo rohtua dna
.tcartnoc eht saw taht ,noillim evif rof ti gniod erew yeht ,yllacinhceT
.ot pu elgguns ot gnitrofmoc dna mraw gnihtemos
”!rednerrus-rednerrus-rednerruS“ ,gnimaercs tpek worceracS taht elihw slaid gnikrow ,snottub ta debbaj ihccurT ”!wonk t’nod I“ ”?did ew fi od annog s’ti kniht ti s’tahW
.detcerroc yrthguaD ”,ris ,ihccurT“
”senihsyeknoM“ fo
?thgil gnikcuf A ?thgiL“
srab tlaboc erom owt dewohs edistuo kool kciuq A
]…ffuts dna sgniht erehw regnahffilc a no dedne ew dna ,ecalp koot stneve dna sretcarahc[ ,emit tsaL ]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[   .sserP pluP orraziB morf
,ekatsim eht derevocsid enoemos enil eht nwod erehwemos ,yltnedivE
”—t’nac tsuj I !hctib-a-fo-nos uoy gniyrt m’I“
,yawa gniggulp tpek nosnegroJ
,ssenkrad eht ni thgil fo hsalf A   2 fo 1 traP ,llewkcoR .B.J yb ”senihsyeknoM“   :yojne esaelP
”?ereh ti s’yhw oS“
etaM tsriF saw eH
erif cirtcele fo slirdnet gnikraps dna
.pihs eht gnikcor ,meht otni dewolp srab eht fo tsrif ehT
”?siht ref diap ’nitteg ew era hcum woH“
duolc derutcarf a diova ot yaw rehto eht gnigdod neht dna
,scitamehcs tnaw I
,mih fo efil eht rof tub ,srewsna eht lla dah ti ekil neercs eht ta wap elttil sih gnibbats
.snoxalk eht ecnelis ot hctiws llik eht gnihcnup ,erows remmahworC ”!timmad gnikcuf doG“
nees reve dah remmahworC tseb eht—rettO saw ,tolip eca na saw eH
guns dna paclluks rehtael sih fo spalfrae eht ta llup ot gnitfil swap eliga
.gnimoc tpek tsuj yeht tub ,ygrene tlaboc fo srewohs ni meht gnitaretilbo
.noitats reh ta yawa gnippat ,dnuora gninrut
”?taht si kcuf eht tahW !ihccurT
.dnammoc ni dnoces enif denmad a saw eh tpecxe
.hO ?tahW“ .detpmorp yrthguaD ”?tsefinam ehT ?niatpaC“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,dehgis ehs ”,dnim reven—urT s’tI“
”—elbirret dna wen tahW ?won ti si tahW“
.deddon remmahworC ”,railimaf sdnuoS“ ”?eid ro nioj
”.hctapeye na htiw namow a etad reveN“
,srats eht morf gnifink eulb tsethgirb fo rab tnaillirb a
”,ris ,ihccurT“ ”—yhcooH“ .edis
.dnuora kcab denrut neht ton ro tlusni na saw taht fi ediced ot gniyrt
”.stnemamra sti lla tog llits s’worceracS eht taht ereht tuo tihs eulb taht lla morf gnisseug m’I dnA“
,detah evah dluohs remmahworC yob ytterp deye-krad ,deriah-krad a—
.pu flesmih dekcip dna dehgis remmahworC  ”!yrros-yrros-yrroS !yrroS“ ”!eigroJ“
.pleh rof gnikool ,etaM tsriF sih ot denrut dna dias eh
tnemom a rof dna
.mottob s’ihccurT ta gnirutseg ,dias eh ”,weiv ehT“ ”?tahW“
”!neht dna won yreve gnihtemos tih gnikcuf ot uoy tcepxe I dna rennug gnikcuf eht er’uoY
”?noitalugeR“ .ni tuc ihccurT
,niatpaC sih no dednuor dna
”?pihs ym no gniod ehs si kcuf eht tahW
hU“ ”?snoitinum ,ni sA .sredipS“
,edis eht ni erauqs nevaR thguac rab eulb A
”.rekcuf taht llik ot woh em llet ot uoy tnaw I
dias uoY ?kcab shtnom wef a su dedraob taht aitiliM fo puorg tahT“
.dedneffo dekool ihccurT  ”?ylsuoireS ?iccuG“
”,ylimaf htiw ssenisub gniod naht esroW
ylniatrecnu detulas ihccurT ”…yakO“
.niks yerg reh gnireppep ,reh otni dehsams sdnuor eulb tlaboc fo duolc a sa deredduhs nevaR
,pu gnirewop smetsys yrellitra
,dnuorg eht ot gnihsarc egdirb eht no esle enoyreve dna remmahworC gnidnes ,revo drah reh dekconk dnoces ehT
.ssa teews avulleh eno tog s’ihccurT ,yas attog I tub ,ykrej a-eceip a htiw detam niart thgierf a ekil tliub s’ehs dna ,og attog hsilop dna tips ehT“
”!rekcuf taht maJ !ti pots oS“
.dellac remmahworC ”!ihccurT .kcuF .eeL .oH“
”.smmoc eht otni deppaT
,detnap nosnegroJ ”,ynam oot-ynam oot-ynam ooT“
.meht fo ynam os tih ylno dluoc snonac eht dna ereht tuo stegrat fo tol a erew ereht tub
,htap a raelc ot tseb sih gniod
gnilggiuqs eht erew sekanS  .deddon yrthguaD
”?pihs ym ta gnitoohs si kcuf eht ohW“
”.did I esruoC“  ”?tsefinam eht kcehc t’ndid uoy naem uoY“
,delley remmahworC ”!?tahW“ !hguoC ”—rettO
,yek a deppat yrthguaD
,ecnetnes-dim ffo tuc eciov s’worceracS ehT
.dniheb esolc gniwollof stnecserc gnikraps ,gnilbmut fo aes a
sdnuor eslup noi decrof fo tohsrettacs a
.]esrevinu eht fo dne ssa eht ta
”!rednerrus-rednerrus-rednerruS
strap )2( owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”?esrevinu nwonk eht ni erehwyna elpmas tnalp tunaep nwonk tsaL“
!yug weN .revetahW“
,gnikeirhs a htiw egdirb s’nevaR gnillif ,demaercs snoxalK
,dias remmahworC ”,elbissopmi kcuF ?elbissopmI“
”.yab ograc eht ni spahc sselssa oN“
”.ssa s’nosnegroJ ekil sknitS“
,meht otni dehsarc
.ti otni dewolp rab eulb rehtona sa yltneloiv gnilbmert
.ecnanossid gnittilps-rae
.neercs reh no tod der gniknilb a ta regnif reh debbaj dna
saw ohw oitaroH
!enoz detcirtser a deretne evah uoY“ .niagA
.seye s’remmahworC gnidiova ylluferac enoyreve
.draobyek reh ta yllacitnarf gnikrow ,drah denworf ihccurT
,yletaidemmi detpure sneriS
,niaga detniop rettO ”?rettO ,uoy otni nettog s’kcuf eht tahW“
”?gnihtyna htiw od ot evah taht seod tahW
.tsefinam eht fo tser eht hguorht dellorcs dna mih ediseb retupmoc eht ot denrut neht
”—ot enihcam htaed cihtapohcysp a deen aitiliM eht dluow yhW“
?saedi ynA ?enoynA“
”?yrthguaD“ .tuoba no gnitteg saw eh tahw tuo erugif t’ndluoc remmahworC
gnirutcel erom ,rettahc fo tsrub rehtonA  .delworg remmahworC ”,em attuo parc eht ’nirob reY .rettO
.daeh eht ni drah nosnegroJ dekcams dna noitats yrellitra eht ot revo deklats ,dnuora delrihw remmahworC ”!eigroJ“  .lluh s’nevaR ssorca tohs erif cirtcele fo stlob sa eulb tlaboc gnicra
.edis eht ni etaM tsriF sih gnigdun ,delims remmahworC ”?he ,dab toN“
.mra ot dediced kraps thgirb emos tub ,senal gnippihs eht gnitisnart srethgierf eht no sbat peek ot dengised yllanigiro erew yehT
.pihs eht no rekaeps yreve morf demaercs eciov cinortcele na
.erih rof seivaeh yratilimarap ,tekram kcalb erew aitiliM
etulas psirc a ffo gnippans
sneris eht dna … !malB  …litnu
.werc sih ta gniralg
.retteb nwonk ev’dluohs remmahworC
.sllih eht rof dedaeh eh sa mih ediseb neercs retupmoc eht ot edistuo srab eulb eht morf gnikcilf seye ,leehw eht gninrut dna
.htuom dehtoot-prahs sih morf sgnirettihc suoludercni dna
,metsys eht deireuq yrthguaD
.toidi uoy ,nug gnikcuf uoy os ’rennug‘ syas noitats ehT“
noitamrofni eht hguorht dennacs remmahworC sa tuhs htuom sih tpek ylesiw neht dna
.yldaed erew yeht noitanibmoc nI
”?nacs egnar gnol no s’ohW
!tihs fo eceip sselesu uoy ,eigroJ ,timmadoG“
,revo devom yrthguaD
.redluohs sih revo dekool yrthguaD elihw noitamrofni eht denimaxe dna revo deklaw remmahworC
,taht lla tog ev’uoy nehw dnA .sworceracS no tog ev’ew gnihtyreve ,smargaid ngised
esoht ,ruoh na naht ssel ni trapa nevaR ekil pihs a ekaT
.mih derehtob llits gniht eno tuB
,lluh kciht-elpirt reh gnidnuop
.meht otni gninnur tpek nevaR ynnepeerhT nosaer emos rof dna ,syad eseht erehwyreve erew yehT
,etaM tsriF sih no dednuor eH ”!yrthguaD
.ot ton ssenisub daB .scisab eht toG .teehs revoc eht daeR
.erac t’noD“ ”.ris ,ihccurT s’tI“
,drah pu decarb dna delrihw ihccurT ”!riS“ ”!eihcooH“ .elihw
,edis eht ot denael dna deddon rettO
?gnihtyna htiw od ot evah noitaluger seod kcuf eht tahW“
,dednamed eh ”?taht saW .kcuf ehT .tahW“
.etsatsid ni gnicamirg ,deredduhs remmahworC ”.sgniht ypeerC .sredips etaH .hguoht
,drocer eht fo gninnigeb eht ot kcab dellorcs rettO
.neercs reh denimaxe dna
niks etisopmoc latem reh gnirocs
,draobyek eht ta deppat yrthguaD ”.ereh esle gnihtemos s’erehT .no gnaH“
.trop ot drah nevaR gnikcor
.delworg remmahworC
.egap tsrif eht no srettel der ,egral rehtar ni nettirw drow elgnis a ta gnitniop ,dias eh ”,sredipS ?eeS“
.lluh s’nevaR dereppep duolc eulb eht fo egde gnidael eht sa hteet rieht gnilttar
.ereh attuo er’eW“
,tnemom a yrthguaD deredisnoc remmahworC ”?huH“
.lrig taht renrael kciuQ .retteB .gnilleY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.derettum remmahworC
.wodniw eht tuo derats dna tsehc sih revo smra sih dedlof remmahworC
.ti kcehc did I tub ,ylluferac toN“
”.gnipeek drocer ta doog yrev saw reven waL .serugiF“
”.oitaroH nisuoc ruoy ot steg ti yllautneve dna ,dneirf a dlot ohw dneirf a dlot
,relgnarw-tac dna relbbircs emit-trap ,llewkcoR .B.J yb
”!namow ,ereht tuo si kcuf eht tahw
.tohs parc a s’nosnegroJ wonk I dnA .me‘ ees I .haey-
” ?dnatsrednu uoy ,su ffo sgniht esoht peeK
snug terrut ,yllacitnarf gnitovip dop yrellitra
.leehw s’pihs dezisrevo eht gninnam wollef yrruf ,reppad eht dna
.hguoht ,thgir s’ehS“
,llewkcoR .B.J yb ”senihsyeknoM“ fo strap 2 fo 1 eht saw sihT    .daed tnew
.kool gnol doog a koot eh sa gnilknirw worb
”.sseug a ekaT“ ”?ohw ot ti dlos-
,eye sih thguac yrthguaD ”.mehA“
,nottub der gib a tsniaga mlap sih demmals dna delrans remmahworC
.seye sih revo ti dellup dna rosiv gnitegrat eht debbarg
”.yllaeR .tnaillirb gnikcuF .eigroJ ,tnaillirB“
,daeh sih ot ylesolc erom ti
laed teews a ekil demees d’ti ,emit eht tA
,yldam detovip nosnegroJ
.noisivid smotsuC s’waL eht fo noitnevni na—
.dereffo dah reyub s’oitaroH noillim evif gnilddip eht naht elbaulav eroM
.sdnuor fo snezod tuo gniyarps
.etal oot saw ti neht yb dna—
.ylitterp os detanoted taht stnecserc gnitator eht snoiprocS ,srab
serots doof ,tnemilpmoc snopaew ,stsefinam ograC“ ”?tahw gninnacS
.ytinutroppo gnisnes ,delims remmahworC
,erif eht fo tuo )sttub dna( pihs rieht llup werc dna remmahworC[ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
oitaroH nisuoC saw esac siht ni ylimaF  .decamirg eh
”!niatpaC ,yrroS .niatpaC ,eyA“
.ekaw rieht ni gniwollof stnecserc gnilbmut fo duolc a htiw ecaps hguorht gnihtirw
”,nom’c-nom’c-nom’C“
.ylimaf htiw ssenisub od reveN !stoidi uoy ,ylimaF—tub
.sdnah sih htiw ecaf sih gnirevoc ,denaorg remmahworC
,ecno rof ,taht ezilaer ot ylno ,gnorw eman reh gnitteg rof tca toir eht mih daer ot ydaer ,regnif a desiar dna
.elbaulav dna ecracs tnaem ’elpmas nwonk
”,su ot mih morf dnA“
”!dnuora gnikcuf pots ,eigroJ ,ti nmaddoG“ ”—tnaw uoy …oS“
”.pu-xim krowrepaP“
”.ereht tuo s’tahw em lleT !eihcooM .revetahW“
”?duol nmaddog os snoxalk esoht era yhW !yrthguaD“ .niagA
.neercs eht no pu drocer dnoces a gnignirb
,dekaeuqs nosnegroJ ”,ris ,eyA“
”.pu sgniht nmad eht gnidnuor erew yeht nehw eno siht dessim yeht sseuG
”.eigroJ ,stif eohs eht fI“ ”!yeH“
,pu gnippihw dnah
.me‘ htiw saw ihccurT“
rab eulb gnikans rehtona ,edistuo hsalf rehtonA ”!tihS—no s’ohW“
thgir saw nosnegroJ
,stnecserc gnilbmut eht gnikirts ,niaga tih dna tih stohs s’nevaR
”.su ta gnitoohs s’revetahw fo egnar attuo teg tsael ta nac ew fi eeS“
.ecaps fo ssenitpme eht ssorca gnihtirw ,gnitsiwt ,gnilggiuqs
esrever lluf otni pihs eht gniworht ,dlot saw eh sa did eh tub
.resolc kcart srab eht gnihctaw
sredluohs yrruf sih derauqs eh sa kcen sih dnuora ti deppihw dna
,ylsuoireS .halb-halb-halB .eruliaf seicepS .sugnuF .thgilB“
kool a kcuns dna revo tperc rettO tub sdnah sih desiar dna dehgis yrthguaD  ”.ti pu devohs kcits citnagig a s’ereht dab ooT
.ledom elor evitisop a hcus gnidivorp rof flesmih detalutargnoc remmahworC
,tuo eye na peek dna ereh re‘ kraP“
.enola gniht citohcysp taht evael ,ereh fo tuo lleh eht teg ot eb dluow od ot gniht trams ehT
,hsilop dna tips lla saw ihccurT  ”.thgiR .ihccurT“  .noitats nacs gnol eht gninnam
yb toohs elissim ygrene gnivom tsaf a tel ot edis eno ot reh gnippils
,noitinumma sa me‘ dekraM .huh-
nevaR tsap delias ,sucof tsol selissim eht tniop emos ta dna yawa gnikcab tpek rettO tub
.em ’niddik ’nikcuf reY
.yobloohcs etirtnoc a ekil
nmaddog uoy ihccurT s’tI“
,sserP dereveS yb
,yvruc dna tfos eb ot desoppus erew nemoW
.eciov yot-ykaeuqs cinortcele ylgniyonna sti ni
.gnilggig detrats neht dna
.roolf eht ot werc eht flah gnikconk
noitats s’ihccurT ot deppets yrthguaD
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.hA“ .neercs eht no pu dellac d’eh drocer atad eht ta detniop dna devaw rettO
.wonk t’noD“  ”.ris ,wonk t’noD“
,meht ot no dekcol nosnegroJ
hcara erew sredips ,dekcehc I tsaL“
.egdirb eht fo tnorf eht gnipparw swodniw gniliec ot roolf eht ta ylsselpleh gnivaw ,mih dlot ihccurT ”,gnihtoN“  ”?iccuG .ereht tuo sI .kcuf ehT .tahW“ .dab gnikcuf ooT
eno ffo raeppasid neht dna ecaps hguorht yaw rieht ehtirw snoiprocS dna sekanS fo hctab hserf a gnihctaw
.hteet sih gnidnirg ,dias remmahworC ”,fles ot etoN“
”—rednerrus-rednerruS“
.dediced remmahworC ”,siht wercS“
dnuora delrihw ihccurT
.eci fo spmul drah ,dloc owt seye eulb
.ti dah yeht thguoht remmahworC
.roolf eht morf pu flesmih gnikcip etaM tsriF sih dnuof dna dnuora deleehw remmahworC ”!yrthguaD“
”.dias ehs sa tsuJ .ris ,thgil gninraW“
,spil sih tsniaga gnippat regnif
,gnihcaorppa tsaf
,derats dna deknilb rettO  ”.srekcuf esoht egdod ot evah annog rey os tihs tih t’nac eigroJ“
”?ti si tahw ,sredips ton s’ti fi ,oS“  ”.din-
?xobkcol ehT ?retfa su tnes nisuoc ruoy gniht tahT“
.mih ta kcab gnirats secaf suovren
pot eht ta sdleif tluafed eht ni gnihtemos ot detniop
?oS“  ”.niatpaC ,aitiliM“
”.ti fo pot no thgiR
.snoitinum elkcis-dna-remmah ,ssa-ytsan
”?ti draug ot worceracS a seriuqer ti tnatropmi os s’taht xobkcol taht ni s’tahW“ .deksa eh
fracs deroloc-maerc a fo dne gniliart eht debbarg eH
.ylippah delims nosnegroJ
”.eno rebmun eluR !eigroJ .esac siht ni on tuB .sey ,lleW .oN“
,ti pota dehcrep selggog s’redlew eht gnitsujda
,swodniw eht hguorht gnirats
a rof esle enoemos ta lley ot dediced eh os ,gnipleh t’nsaw ylraelc nosnegroJ ta gnilleY
”.ti dlos yeht ,ti ssim t’ndid waL
.sredips dleh esac taht thguoht ohw eno ylno eht t’nerew uoy yltnerappA“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”!sgniht esoht addir tog waL eht thguohT !yrthguaD
taps ehs ”!worceracS“
dnoces elbissop tsal eht litnu ton—gnimoc ti was reven
.syawedis dewels nevaR sa
.tuoba reh thguorb eh sa edis reh otno nevaR gninrut raen nmad ,revo ti deluah dna
”!yrthguaD“ .erows eh
”,hguone s’tahT .thgirlA“ ”.rettO ,nam dooG
.dne eht ot yaw eht lla depmuj drocer ehT
,nevaR ynnepeerhT otni demmals rab eulb ehT
,sredips was I ecno ’nidaer deppotS
.neercs eht no noitamrofni eht ta gnitniop fo stol dna
.yleugav dnah eno gnivaw ,dias remmahworC
.egnahc a rof thgir enog gnihtemoS .hajulellaH
.ihccurT ,strahc rats tnaw I“
gnisruc dna gnilley
”,ris ,noitaluger s’thgil gninraW“
daeh sih gnikcud
.syob yreviled deifirolg eb yllaitnesse ot hsac fo daw taf a—
,deraeppa srab tlaboc erom owT
,gnitfil dnah eno
,ylthgirb deralf thgiL
.detacav yltnecer dah remmahworC riahc ekil-enorht eht fo mra eht no thgil der gniknilb a ot deddon
gnikcehc sdrawretfa dna
denworf dna neercs txen eht ot gnigap
”!ecarb-ecarb-ecarB“
”.ylevol ydoolb tsuJ .ylevoL“
.ylsuoiruf gnihsulb skeehc
?ton lleh eht yhW
.pu kcip ot tnes neeb dah werc reh dna nevaR gniht yrev eht revo gnihctaw enihcam htaed IA eht noitnem ot deliaf wohemos dah tey dna waL
em llet tsuJ .nmaddog doog a evig t’nod I—iccuiL-amaM -ihcoom yeknom-ihccurT-iccuG“ ”—
.yek elgnis a gnikirts
etam s’rennug saw nosnegroJ
”?rof og esrevinu eht ni tnalp tunaep nwonk tsal eht seod hcum woH“
”!ffo me‘ peek gnikcuf os ,su ffo me‘ peek dias I !?eigroJ ,kcuf eht tahW“
.thgil eralf dna hsalf eht ni gnirettilg sesnel
saw eh semitemos tub ,rennug dab flah a t’nsaw nosnegroJ
,delap dna deplug nosnegroJ
.sreggirt eht ezeeuqs dluoc sdnah mah sih sa tsaf sa erif noi decrof tuo gniruop dna gnihtyreve gnikcart
allevon driew/larutanrepus eht dna
,ecaps ytpme tsuj s’tI“
”.ti htiw xobkcol eht yortsed ll’ew ,tuo worceracS eht ekat ew fI“ ”?gninaeM“
,nworf lauteprep a ni dexif ecaf
tuo deweps dna smsinahcem gnirif niwt eht dezeeuqs eh sa yltfos gnimmuh
tsaL‘  .nihc sih gnibbur ,dias remmahworC ”,gnitseretni s’taht woN .huH“  .deddon rettO
”.ti teg ot smetsys ruo hguorht gnilwarc sti ,ti eman uoy—