.rettO ,uoy
.oot esiar a detcepxe rettO ,yltnerappA
”,werc ym ot revo emoc ot eciohc ruoY“
”?ti yrt ot hguone diputs eb annog s’kniht ay od ohw tsuJ
.ooh-’nikaerf-ooB“ ”!won smmoc on tog ev’ew tuB“
”.lrig ,tuo ti tipS
,dluoc ehs tseb sa ti hguorht mih deklat ihccurT .eroc gnitegrat eht htiw ytluciffid emos gnivah tub ni saw rettO
”!enutrof ydoolb a em gnisuac si sihT !haG“
,erehwon morf deraeppa sekanS
.uoy neht ,tsrif reH“
:siht ot nwod semoc lla tI .rettO ,kooL“
.yltneitapmi delworg eh
tnatropmi ylralucitrap si ,esac siht ni ,hcihw—werc eht fo tsellams eht er’uoy
.roolf eht ot lla meht werht edis s’nevaR no tih drah A ”—tsomlA“
.yawa detsalb srennug terrut eht elihw erif sti gnidael
,reivaeh tog erif s’worceracS eht ni resolC
.tnemeerga elohw siht knihter ot gnitrats rettO
.sessa rieht pu skcits htiw seno nevE
.detcejbo nosnegroJ ”!oN“ ”.paws a ekam dluoc ew esoppus I tub“
.siht tuoba gnihtyna ekil hcum t’noD“
,edistuo dekool dna
.daeh eht fo ekahs etarepsed
.ti drawot gniltruh epahs etihw
!enihcam gnillik a ot esolc elgguns dna
”.gniod erew uoy revetahw gniod eunitnoc…uoy fo tser ehT !ni :ihccurT !tuo :nosnegroJ .yawyna detarrevo s’gnidaeR“
.smmoc eht dereves dna edur gnihtemos dekrab rettO
,gniL ,eigroJ“ ”.ris ,eyA“
.delkcuhc remmahworC
,neht mih ees dluoc remmahworC  .lleh sa deracs ,deyonna ,yrgna—rettahc fo tsrub A ”!rettO“
.dne s’lotsip sih morf ekoms fo lruc a gniwolb
.deknilb remmahworC ”.stnemamrA“
.detcepxe eh rewsna eht etiuq toN
.]dellik sevlesmeht teg etiuq-ton-tub-tsomla ot syaw gnitseretni dna wen dnif werc sih dna remmahworC[ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.daeh sih koohs dna gnihtemos derettum yrthguaD
,ekaw sih ni gniwollof ihccurT htiw yawa derettiks rettO  ”.gir sih otni mi‘ teg dna yab ograc eht ot nwod rettO ekaT !ihccurT“ .ti evol seidal eht llA
.ereh attuo lleh eht su teg dna yrthguaD ,ti tuhS“ ”—riS“
,yb depmuts nosnegroJ
”?em tog ,ti rednu gnignah yrrebelgnid eht dna ssa s’enihcam htaed taht no sucof tsuj aY .ereht tuo ffahc taht fo enon tuoba yrrow ay t’nod os erif revoc edivorp ll’srennuG .worceracS eht ta thgir ay toohs ,tuo ay tohsgnils ,hctah retuo eht nepo ll’I dna sdnoces ytrihT .thgiR .ti dexif tahT
”.’niksa ref sknahT .oitaroH ,elbirret gnikcuf tsuJ
,detiaw eh neht dnA
.eseht no ecnanetniam krow ot desU“
.elbapac tsom eht dna—
,eruces daolyaP“
.eno redrah eht rof won
”.’nitseggus rey tahw od ot hguone esolc teg ew fi seceip ot nevaR raeT .etarucca no-gnab dna demra ylivaeh s’rekcuF“
.delley remmahworC
.degnahc dah gnihtyreve dnuof
,worceracS eht fo mottob eht ot yeknom ynit a ekil gnignilc
,neht elihw a rof teiuQ
”—esrow dellac neeB .haey-haeY“
tiusecaps a no parts ot werc ym a-eno ’niksa reY“ ”—krow nac tI“
.desuma kool t’ndid ihccurT
,owt gnimoceb etunim eno
.gniht eno rof ,uoy rof xobkcol nmad taht gnitteg roF“ .dednamed remmahworC ”?tahw reF ?uoy ewO“ ”.em ewo uoY
—sesuoh sa efas eb d’eh worceracS eht ot tog rettO ecnO
,hcuols yrgna ,debmil-esool a otni devloved ecnats yratilim ,digir eht
.kniw a gnippord ,dias remmahworC
”!niatpaC ,gniyrT“ ”!navilluS“
,seye gnirats ediW
.detaeper remmahworC ”,AVE“
”,ti ekil annog s’eigroJ erus toN  ”—tuB“
.worceracs a ekil lla ta gnihton dekool ti dna ,gniht eht no seye nettog d’yeht emit tsrif eht saw tI
.swodniw drawrof eht pu til erif eulB
.modnar ta gnirif s’worceracS .modnaR“ ”.hO“
.trapa meht erot gniht taht erofeb htiw revo siht teg ot emiT
.uoy tug annog m’I dna
tolip eht ta deralg remmahworC
,snoitcejbo erom llatserof ot eciov sih gnisiar ,dias eh ”,ro
—diputs t’nsaw rettO
,mih ta kcab gnirats secaf dekcohs nezod flah a dnuof dna dnuora decaf eH
,klim sa elap gninrut ecaf
.edis s’nevaR ni eloh eguh a erot wor a ni stih tcerid owT
,lluh s’nevaR tsniaga gnidduht tohs retfa tohs ,net gnimoceb
”!worceracS nmaddog taht tuoba em llet ot derehtob d’uoy fi elbirret enog evah ton thgim ti esruoC“
.neercs eht tsniaga pitregnif reh fo paT ”.erehT“
”,tol a me‘ sekiL
”.rehtona rof ,eseehc ssiwS otni tolip ruoy gninrut morf worceracS cainam taht gnipeek roF
.worceracS eht tegroF“
”.ereht tsomlA“ .dias ihccurT ”,ris ,seY“
.su ta gnirif s’worceracS gnikcuf eht wonk I .haey-haeY“ .wodniw eht edistuo eulb fo stops eht ta gnitniop ,dias yrthguaD
?nevaR ynnepeerhT ?worceracS“
,meht dnuora sepahs eulb eht ta yawa gnidnuop ,gnirif detrats snug thgie llA .resned
,detacav dah eigroJ dop delabmig eht ot revo dedaeh dna
”.daer nac eh erus neve toN .hcet nacs elbirroh a s’nosnegroJ .aedi tseb eht eb ton thgim tahT“
.ti fo tuo tohs dah taht etihw fo pilb eht ton dna
,sedis reh gnola erot sekanS
snug yna evah ot desoppus t’nsaw nevaR ynnepeerhT ,gnikaeps yltcirtS
”?rettO ot klat annog ew esle woH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
pihs eht no sucof dluow ti os erif s’worceracS eht gniward
,yenom adaol tihs a rof lles ot ograc a tog eW
.yab ograc eht ni smmoc lanretni eht gnisu dellac ihccurT ”,ris
.revo decnalg dna denworf yrthguaD ”?ynnuf gnihtemoS“
.egnellahc ni gnirats ,tsehc reh revo smra reh gnidlof ,dias ihccurT
enutrof fo hcraes ni ffo tes yeht-
1202 ni esaeler rof eud osla gniK nosmirC allevon driew/larutanrepus eht dna
.neercs niam eht ot deef aremac tfa eht thguorb yrthguaD ”!eyA“
,yppup sih dekcik tsuj dah enoemos ekil gnikool
”.ti dednilb dratsab elttil tnecifingaM“
”.dnilb yletelpmoc eb ll’worceracS
heH .heH“  .neeb dah worceracS s’aitiliM eht erehw sirbed fo duolc gnitaolf a tub gnihton saw ereht
,derettum eh ”,ees ot gnihton ,ees ot gnihton ,ees ot gnihtoN“
) etaceH dna ,sratS dna kraD ,itegnereS(
.deffuh remmahworC ”,eniF
.esool emac gnihtemoS
.neercs eht no deraeppa ecaf ylwoj ,taf
1202 ni esaeler rof eud saeS tnatsiD & sratS nettogroF levon gnimocpu eht
.niaga gnikrow trats ot dediced yeht litnu snottub ta gnibbats ,noitats smmoc eht ta dekcik eH
yltnangidni dekaeuqs rettO
.egdirb eht ssorca lla secaf knalB
,ynit s’rettO eciton t’ndluow worceracS eht gniyarp
.egdirb eht ssorca deirruh dna
”.sesiarevig t’nod I tub ,ereh wen rey wonk I“
”- xirtam latsyrc desuf a ,ytilibapac gninnacs laretalib htiw eborp IA suomonotua-imes noitisop dexif a s’ti ,lleW“
.ecno ta srennug eht lla ot gnikaeps ,dias remmahworC
.dednamed remmahworC
,spil sih tsniaga regnif a deppat remmahworC
”,ihccurT ,em ot klaT“
.ytefas ro seiboob
.ni reh ekat dna worceracS eht ta nevaR tniop navilluS dah remmahworC
”.pu wohs annog m’I nehw ’nirednow skeew ref skcirb ’nittihs eb ll’eH ?I t’ndid
.ereht detlob si xobkcoL .ti toohs t’naC“
”.gnissim si yot rieht seciton aitiliM eht emit eht yb enog gnol eb annaw I dna
”?rettO s’erehW ?eh si erehW“
”!t’ndid I fi em llik ot denetaerht uoY“
.yawyna meht fo tsom ot ,lleW
”?’niod ew woH !rettO“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uo Y
,detiaw dna htaerb sih dleh remmahworC
.ylippahnu deralg ihccurT
”.emit siht flesym deniartseR
”!won enilffo rekcuf taht deen I !rettO !rettO“
.noitats smmoc delddir-tellub eht ta bmuht a gnikooh
,redro gnikrow reporp ni eb ot demrifnoc gnihtyreve dna
.eno doog a deen ylirassecen t’ndid yeht tub—
.daeh reh koohs ihccurT
mrof detius-ecaps s’rettO morf gnikcilf ezag
”—ssa sih teg dna ihccurT htiw dnuora ’nikcuf pots ot mi‘ lleT .yab ograc eht morf rettO teg oG
,ylduol gnirettahc ,daeh sih koohs dna
”.hctib-a-fo-nos a er’uoy syas rettO dnA“
.ylsuovren deksa yrthguaD ”?gniod eh s’woH“
.smotsuC hguorht teg dluoc yeht os tnempiuqe snoitacinummoc
.seloh ynit htiw ti gnikramkcop
.eson s’nevaR ssorca erocs snoiprocS nezod a flah gnihctaw ,delworg eh
,daeherof sih no demoolb taewS
.retfa setunim wef a navilluS gninway
”,aedi tnaillirB !esnesnoN“
.snoitats lla morf tnemegdelwonkcA  ”.rettO affo me‘ peek
.esop retto cioreh ,evarB
,enas s’ti gniyas neve toN
,smra sih dedlof eH
tnemegdelwonkca ni wap a desiar rettO  .meht retfa dellac remmahworC
.hguorht tog llits selissim s’worceracS eht fo wef a
,mih fo tnorf ni flesreh dekrap dna
.deton yrthguaD ”,tniop a toG“
.deksa yrthguaD ”?gnitseggus uoy er’tahw oS“
,devlos melborp enO
.pihs eht ylf ot mih deen yeht taht etaM tsriF eht gnidnimer
.yawa lotsip sih tup ,sdnah sih daerps remmahworC ”?tahW“
,relgnarw-tac dna relbbircs emit-trap
”,ti od uoy woh si siht ,tuo worceracS taht ekat annaw uoy tub
.noitats smmoc eht ni eloh hserf eht ta
fo strap )2( owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”,ti ot desu teg uoY .sselkcer tsuJ .haN“ .dehtaerb ihccurT
rettO eveirter ot AVE ihccurT dnes ot hguone esolc tog yllautneve yeht tub
.yawa deirruh ehs sa ylippah deltsihw gniL ”.niatpaC ,eyA“
,yalpsid s’tiusecaps sih ot snoitcurtsni gniltnamsid dna smargaid gnidnes
.mleh eht ta bmuht a dekooh dna
.delworg eh ”,ihccurT ,netsiL“ .mleh ta ecalp sih gnimuser ,yawa deppils dna detliw eh litnu
”.tihs htrow t’nia syug eseht a-tser ehT
,eyA“ ”!pu rettO kcip nac ew os rekcuf taht htaenrednu pu emoC
.tnelis saw egdirb ehT
,gnimmuh llits saw nosnegroJ
.detnaw ehs tahw dnuof ehs litnu smargaid hguorht gnikcilc ,dias ehs ”,gnihtemos derebmemer I ,uoy rof ykcuL“
”!mleh ekat nac eh os deb attuo navilluS llor enoemos evah dnA“
.margaid eht gniyduts ,esolc gninael
.noitats mleh ytpme yrev a gnivael
sterrut eht ni si esle reveohw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.sterrut drawrof eht morf stohs htiw pu mih dekcab zeuqzaV dna gniL elihw
,leehw eht ot gnulc navilluS
,ecneitap fo tol a dna ,gnirevuenam luferac emos koot tI ”!ris
”.gniwollof toN“ ”.siht fo llA“
”,heh-heH .heH“ .elbmur ssab sih ni topaeT elttiL a m’I ekil ylsuoicipsus dednuos taht gnihtemos tuo gnizzub
.llik ot elbissopmi tuoba tsuj s’ti snaem hcihw ,enihcam htaed deromra-revo ,derewop-repus ,ssa-naem a s’tI ?smret s’namyaL“ .ecnayonna ni denworf ihccurT ”.ihccurT ,hsilgnE“
.tnangidni dekool ihccurT
,worceracS eht dnuor dna dnuor nevaR gninrut
.thguoht eh ,hsif reffup a ekil eroM
.dewollof ecnelis elbatrofmocnu ,gnol
”.tnemyolpme ym fo rettam eht s’ereht neht dnA“
.taht tcepser attoG ?he ,snug giB“
.ti llik ot woh wonk ot detnaw uoy dias uoY .kooL“
.ereh ni meht gnignirb ni ytinas sih gninoitseuq detrats remmahworC
.reh ediseb neercs eht ta gnibbats rehto eht ,evruc sti no gnitser dnah eno ,tuo dekcik pih
.kcus syug uoy nmaD“
.werc eht no esle enoemos ot mleh eht ta ecalp detevoc sih revo gninrut tnaem ti ecnis yllaicepsE
.detuohs ihccurT ”,daeh ym no ytnuob a gnivah fo rettam llams eht tsuj s’erehT .wonk t’nod I ,hO“
.slivederad sekil ammE ,etaK ot gnidroc’ woN“
.tnangidni dekool ihccurT ”!?ti tuoba knihT“
.detsisni remmahworC
”?taht od ot hguone esolc teg ot desoppus ew era lleh eht woh tsuj dnA“
”.smmoc deen t’ndid ew dias uoy thguohT“
.gnitalp ta gniraet ,lluh s’nevaR otni peed gnirocs ,hguorht gnitteg tpek erif nruter erom tub
,delley remmahworC ”,taht xif ot ereh pu enoemos teG !yrthguaD
.suoreficov dna etaidemmi erew snoitcejbo ehT  ”.rettO ,pu tiuS“
– enihcam raw a ton ,lla retfa rethgierf a saw ehs—
remmahworC .detsisni yrthguaD ”,kooL .niatpaC“
t’noW“ ”?yaw taht ti no pu kaenS ?ti htaenrednu ni emoc eW“
.edisni kcab meht gnirb dna xobkcol eht dna
”!mih no aremac a teG !yrthguaD“
.tuo ’nittips s’ti snoiprocS dna sekanS eht no sucoF
.eigroJ ,nam eht draeh uoY“
”!ysub rekcuf taht peeK !syob ,thgirlA“
”!setunim ytnewt tsal eht rof su ta gnirif neeb s’ti—nietsniE ,hsalf sweN
,dehctip dna deredduhs pihs eht
sa nwod dekram meht fo eno tsal yreve ,slluh rieht nwod dna pu gniltsirb sterrut ,demra erew srethgierf eht lla ,yllaiciffonU
”?taht ni ynori eht sees ohw eno ylno eht I mA
!aH“  .tnemegdelwonkca ni krab elgnis A  ”?rettO .spoO“
dnayawa gnitsalb sterrut thgie lla
”—t’ndid I—did I“
”.eno taht ebyam tpecxE
.dennalp dah yeht tahw rof toN
Ayas ot dah ihccurT tahw raeh ot gnitiaw enoyreve
.yb deklaw ehs sa remmahworC rof kool gums a gniraps
,sserP dereveS yb
,denediw seye s’oitaroH
,dehceercs dna deredduhs pihs ehT
tpeC‘ .werc siht ni lla ta romuh a-esnes oN
.smmoc eht tsniaga dnah sih gnimmals ,demaercs remmahworC ”!rettO !rettO“  .wodniw s’egdirb eht edistuo ecaps fo hcterts derettulc eht gnihcraes ,deirc yrthguaD ”!mi‘ tsoL“
”.dereffo uoy noillim evif eht naht erom tol avulleh a htrow saw ograc taht wenk uoy ekil tsuJ .nisuoc ,did uoY“
.ylwols gniddon ,margaid eht ta gnireep ,dias yrthguaD
,uoy dnif annog m’I .kcuF .elttiL .taf uoy em ot netsil uoy woN“ .dooG
.delims yrthguaD ”,dnilb s’tI
,esnopser ni esion fo rettahC
taorht sih deraelc yrthguaD
”?mi‘ llik annog yllaer uoY“
.yltnedifnoc dias yrthguaD ”,AVE“
,nepo gnignah htuom
,llewkcoR .B.J yb ”senihsyeknoM“ fo strap 2 fo 2 eht saw sihT    .delims remmahworC ”,thgirla reY .ihccurT ,thgirla reY .yksirf ,hoO“
.derepsihw remmahworC ”,nom’c-nom’c-nom’C“  .raems
.stnecserc gnikraps dna srab eulb ta yawa gnitsalb ,gnirif snug lla htiw dnuora pihs eht gnignirb ,revo drah ti gninrut
demaercs remmahworC ”!kcuF“
”?god a evah uoy oD
neewteb ecaps fo hcterts eht tuB
.wodniw eht tuo gnitniop ,dias remmahworC ”,sihT“
,delpmur a dna setunim evif ni egdirb eht no hcet a dah yehT ”.ris
detarea…uoY ?rebmemer ,smmoC“ .niaga yrthguaD ”?niatpaC ,mU“   ”!rettO“
.egdirb s’nevaR ynnepeerhT revo delttes—ecnelis etelpmoc—ecneliS
.tib a snoiprocS eht gninniht fo boj tneced a enod d’eh tub
”,ssa nwo sti fo tuo ees t’nac ti ,naem uoY“
,nwod dnah sih demmals remmahworC
.ecaf sih ssorca dekcarc mlap s’ihccurT  .ssa teews ,teews reh dehcnip dna tuo dnah a dekans remmahworC
.mottob s’eborp eht desolc taht hctah eht ta yawa gnittuc
.ti fo enon gnivah saw dna
.niks latem reh gnola gnicar erif cirtcele
”,kooL“ ”!?tahW“ ”?niatpaC“
.ti elbasiD“  ”.ti elbasiD“
,hguoht mih attuo suseejeb eht deracS .haN“
”?kniht ayaddahW“ .ecaf sih ssorca gnihcterts gnilims
”.ammE htiw stniop emos teg dna pu kcas nac uoy“
,drah gnikniht ,sdnah sih gnurw rettO
gnitfird a otni rettO nrut dluoc hcihw fo eno yna ,selissim eulb tlaboc htiw dellif saw
.thgiR .hO“ ”?meht
.ti fo og hguot a gnivah saw reggub elttil roop eht tub
.rettO ,ni ’niog rey ,rehtona ro yaw enO“ .ffo mih gnittuc
.noitats smmoc eht dehcnup dna
…elbissop s’taht fI .gohegdeh a htiw detam elahw a rO
,egdirb eht otno demrots ihccurT ”.esiar a tnaw I“
,ti gnirocs ,ti gnitned
”senihsyeknoM“   :yojne esaelP
,tuoba emac nevaR sa worceracS eht drawot mih gnignils ,egasuas elttil taf a ekil tuo rettO taps yehT ”.rettO ,lleh me‘ eviG“
noitcafsitas fo kaeuqs A
.ylsuoiruf gnilggiw slwoj taf
”?ynnuf siht sdnif rettO tub eno oN ?ylsuoireS“
.ecaf sih nwod deruop
,llewkcoR .B.J yb ”senihsyeknoM“
,derettuts eh ”,tahw-tahw-tahW“
,dnuora gninrut ,deksa eh ”?oS“
”.tops dnilb a tog s’ti
?ti ssiK ?neht tahw oS“ ”.emit fo etsaw a lla si siht dna worceracS eht htiw xobkcol eht yortsed uoy ,ti toohs uoY
.no denrut tib a t’nsaw eh dias eh fi gniyl eb d’remmahworC
”.ssa eht ni ti toohs ot tog ev’I .ssa s’tI“
…erif gnirevoc erom elttil a htiw spahreP
.smmoc tiusecaps fo zzub dna kcilc railimaf eht yb deinapmocca srekaeps eht hguorht deretlif rethguaL
erutcip yrev eht—tuo dekcik pih eno
”.ereht tuo rekcuf taht llik ot woh tuo erugif ot deen tsuJ“
.won dessip no-lluf saw ihccurT  ”.woh si sihT
.deton yrthguaD ”,doog hcum su od yllaer t’now sterrut drawrof eht ,ereht ni er’ew ecnO“
,yzarc dnoyeb saw nalp siht wenk eh
.dehgis yrthguaD ”,ris ,eyA“
.tnemom a thguoht dna deppots remmahworC ”.tiaW .sruoy fo efiw decaf-gorf taht tug annog m’I nehT
,dnah a desiar remmahworC tub ni tuc rettO  ”.evah stiusecaps rehto eht a-enon taht sgiw-
.reh rof gniht a dah rettO dna—stit ecin fo tes dna nug gib a htiw namow eew a—
.t’ndid ehs tpircsnart laiciffo reh ot gnidrocca dna
.snoitats terrut eht ot nwod dellac remmahworC
!malB ”—syas osla eH“
,aitiliM eht ot sknaht“
,gnirif snug eerht htiw neve tub ,rehtegot gnikrow boj doog a did yehT
.drah noitats eht dekcik remmahworC
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.sdop thgie lla llif dna dnif nac uoy reveohw barG“
”.aedi eht teg uoy tub ecaps ni hcum snaem yllaer taht taht toN
.ihccurT ,stub on em tuB“
.spil taf ta gnikcil eugnot knip detaolb
tuo taps worceracS eht snoiprocS dna sekanS eht egdod dna ni meht ediug ot tolip a deen d’yeht—esruoc fo ,thgir saw eH
,erif tlaboc fo sevaW
2 fo 2 traP ,llewkcoR .B.J yb
,devaew dna degdod navilluS
,tep a tog uoY .rettam t’nseoD
remmahworC ot revo dehcram
.gnikrow t’nerew ylneddus hcihw smmoc eht ta gnidnuop ,yldeticxe delley remmahworC ”!rettO !rettO“
.denekrad ecaf s’remmahworC
.mra s’remmahworC ta deggut yrthguaD ”?ris ,mmU“
.ecaps ni gnignah worceracS eht fo gnolbo suonimo eht ot
.reh deksa remmahworC
,tnelis tnew sterrut eht emit eht yb dna
.smmoc lanretni dellik ylnO
.ecnats s’ihccurT deipoc dna reh ediseb ni deppils rettO
.nemow yssas dekil eH
.noitats smmoc eritne eht hcum ytterp dna
,tib eno ti ekil t’ndid eh raelc ti edam ecaf gnituop s’nosnegroJ ta ecnalg a
.roiretsop sti htaeneb tops dnilb taht ni neddih
pu kcab teg ot detrats remmahworC
.seye sih revo nwod selggog sih dellup eh sa tsehc sih tuo deffup dna
.gniklat tpek dna kool ruos a mih evag ihccurT
.smmoc eht otni gniyek ,dellac remmahworC ”?rettO ,ydaer uoY“
”.wonk uoy ,smaet gnihctiws srebmem sti ot yldnik ekat yltcaxe t’nseod aitiliM“
noitats reh denodnaba gniL ”.ris
,syawedis pihs eht dehctip tih rehtona tub
thguondaerD no etaM tsriF saw ammE
,revo deklaw remmahworC
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,yllufetarg derettahc rettO
.nemwerc eht fo tser eht yb dehsuhs ylkciuq saw dna detcejbo enoemoS
feilebsid ni gnirats ,dnuora delrihw yrthguaD
”!revo em wercs taht tihs fo skcas gniyl htiw od I tahw s’taht zuC .pihs ym fo tnorf eht no daeherugif a ekil uoy tnuom dna—
.trap suoregnad eht saw sihT
.dehsinav elims s’oitaroH
.delims remmahworC ,og ay erehT
”,ereh attuo su teG !navilluS“
”.koob ym ni seca reY
,yltnatropmi eroM
”?noitomorp fo dnik tahW“
suoirolg tub devil-trohs saw tI
nur skcehc AVE-erp lla htiw ,tiusecaps sih otni depparts saw rettO nehw dnA
”?yob ybab suoicerp s’retsis ruoY ?doolb dna hself nwo ruoY“
edis eno no tikloot a htiw dettiftuo neeb dah gir s’rettO
.ysae eb ll’ti uoy gnillet ton m’I“
.ecno ta lla ,seciov thgiE ”.ris ,eyA“
.dellac remmahworC
,delbmurg remmahworC ”,flesym gnihtyreve od attoG .nmad doG“
,ereht tuo sekanS esoht fo eno nmad elgnis a tih ot deganam t’ndah etam s’rennug ehT
,seY“ .yltalf dias remmahworC
”.emoc modgnik ot rekcufrehtom taht wolb—
.secnats fo ylniatpaC tsom sih gnimussa
,tuo dehcterts emiT
.yletaidemmi tsomla detrats gnitoohs ehT
.delims remmahworC
?gnihtynA ?anaugI ?hsiF ?taC“
,detfil wap ,ezorf rettO
dluoc eh sa tsaf sa gnirif ,yawa deggulp nosnegroJ .meht dniheb esolc gniwollof snoiprocS fo duolc esned a
.ylirgna gnirettahc
,sserP dereveS morf
,lluh s’nevaR tsniaga derettahs snoiprocS
.worceracS eht ot resolc delias ehs sa tih retfa tih gnikat
”.siht ekil annog ton er’uoY“
.reh dlot remmahworC ”,yawyna
.esitrepxe reh detsuahxe gnivah ,deggurhs ihccurT
.dnuora denrut dna rood egdirb eht ta deppots gniL  ”.gniL ,no gnaH“
efiw a llac uoy ssa a-eceip yggorf ,taf taht dna uoy—uoy ffuts annog m’I neht dnA .oot taht tug annog m’I
,eyA“ ”.sterrut drawrof eht ot nwod sessa rieht gahs ot me‘ llet dna zeuqzaV dna drageruaeB barG .gniL“
,peed a werd dna seye sih desolc
,ylthgirb gniralf redlew cra
”?gniog boj taht s’woH !nisuoC !nihP“
!dnuora su gnirB !navilluS“
smmoc deen t’noD
”?taf lrig ym llac tsuj uoY“ ”.tops
”.yrthguaD ,dekcarc reY“
.nevaR affo me‘ peeK
,llew…siht ekil gnihtemoS“
”.nacs revo ekat dna dop taht fo tuo ssa luaH
.ecaf eht ni yrthguaD hcnup t’ndluow eh os net ot gnitnuoc ,htaerb gnimlac
.edutitta dab ffo dessip fo
”?tnemyolpme ruoy htiw gnorw s’tahw tsuj dnA“
”,yrthguaD ,ti xiF“ ”—erus ton m’I…mmU“
.dnah ta boj eht rof flesmih gniydaer ,ffo tuc rettO dna
ihccurT .snottub ta gnikop ylmodnar detrats dna nacS gnoL otni dils
.dop sih ni nosnegroJ gnieye
”.ycnaf reh hctac ot erus s’taht
”,enasni s’eH“ ”?melborP“
.pu s’bmuht a mih evag ihccurT
,enog erew ’sris‘ ehT
”,ereht ni er’ew ecno erif suounitnoc tnaw I“
.edisni eroc gnitegrat eht ot ssecca uoy sevig taht mottob eht no hctah a s’erehT
”.naidemoc gnikcuf a tsuj uoy t’nera lleW
-T latipac a htiw elbuort otni nar remmahworC[ ,emit tsaL
.ecaps fo diov tsav eht gnillif sdnuor noi decrof dna selissim ygrene gnicra fo noisufnoc a
.enil ffo reh gniwels dna
izooh dna sah-ooh ,sdad-od a-stros lla tog sah sruoy fo gir tahT“
.ediw hctah yab ograc eht gniworht
.neercs eht ta gnitniop ,dias ehs ”erehT“ ”?erehW“
.smmoc eht no rettahC
,tuo eroc eht ekaT
.drawnwod tpecxE .snoitcerid lla ni erif fo dleif eerged 063 a tog ,ecalp ni dexif s’gnihT“ ”.’ninetsil m’I“
]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[  .sserP pluP orraziB morf
.daeh sih koohs yrthguaD
.revo taht gnikniht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ssenisub suoires saw siht—won dnuora gnissem oN
.elbirreT“ .delims oitaroH
.tegrat taf eciN .gib s’nevaR“
.swap tnorf sih htiw etarepo dluoc eh taht swalc ekil-recnip owt dna
.secnelis elbatrofmocnu ,gnol detah remmahworC
railimaf a litnu yltneitapmi gnippat eot
pu flesmih werd rettO esuaceb tuo now seiboob yltnerappA
seires itegnereS eht fo rohtua dna
]yrtnes godhctaw IA ,degnared ylthgils a yb no derif gnitteg pu dedne dna
.tops dnilb taht htiw neve ,reh ssim ll’worceracS taht yaw oN
.tegrat elgnis a ta nosinu ni gnirif sterrut thgiE
.gniht erom eno tsuj sevael tahT .tes s’rettO .tes era stnemamrA .thgiR“  .deraeppasid dna rotavele eht otni delip ihccurT dna eh sa
.ylteiuq deksa yrthguaD
.daed erew yeht dettimda tey t’ndah ohw hsif ekil ,dehtuom nepo dna deye-ylgoog lla
,nottub a dekop dna dellac remmahworC ”!ytrihT“ .etal ooT
.yltfos dehgual remmahworC ”,heh-
”.tuoba kniht ll’I
,citamehcs a pu gnillup ,dedda ehs ”,tuB
,reh dniheb pu depip eciov s’rettO
?oot edis reh no er’uoy os ,hO“
,tius taht otni uoy ffuts ereht ihccurT evah dna ,siht od ot uoy redro nac I rehtie woN
”.esaelp uoy sa taen yawa pils dna xob eht gans nac ew ,enog s’taht ecnO“
yrotciv ni delims
.yrthguaD ,enO .tohs enO“
enil eht gnillik
.deggurhs remmahworC
.modnar ta tuo dna ni gnittuc ot enorp—hctilg ylbadnatsrednu erew yeht tub smmoc eht xif ot deganam dah hcet ehT .gnihtoN ”?rettO“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.daeh reh gnikahs ,dias ehs ”,krow
.tsehc sih tsniaga wap a gnipmuht erofeb thgir ti dah eh erus ekam ot dekcehc eH
.deggurhs yrthguaD
revo yawflah reh gnillor
,duolcrednuht a ekil ecaf ,dedlof smra
:tseretni tseb sih ni saw tahw ediced ot deirt eh sa swodniw eht ot remmahworC morf gnitfihs seye
seye sih denepo eH ”?tahW“
”?eannetna sti ni sgnihton teews repsihW
.smmoc deen ew esruoC‘ ?tahW“
.kcis eb ot tuoba saw eh ekil dekool oitaroH
”,toohs ot erehw wonk t’noW“
?remmahworC gnikcuf s’eman yM
.neht ,noitomorp a tnaw I .eniF“