.elbatrofmoc oot elttil a teg ot ti detnaw eh ,gnihtyna fI
.ylimaf sih dna mih fo saw maerd siH
"?naem neve taht seod tahW
.ylleb s'gnihtemos ni won saw ffo gnignah lesrom ynA
.wap gnihca sih ta kcab dekool neht tub "!oN"
".derit m'I .deb ot ttub ruoy teg tsuj ,syawynA .erons I"
,eert eht morf tuo gnippetS
,gniyas erofeb gniwollaws ,dewehc eh sa thguoht eH
.wap sih gnidloh roolf eht no gnittis saw
.ti kaerb ot hguone drah ton tub
",kaeps uoy erofeb gniwehc hsiniF"
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.dnuorg eht ffo gnitteg ,dias eh ",tup yatS"
.nug eht derif eh revenehw tsael eht truh taht tops eht saw tI
.trams oot saw tI
.revoc rieht wolb thgim gnivom
.emac yeht yaw eht ot kcab gnikool ,deksa eh
".erons uoy dias uoY"
.wap a devaw enip ehT
,evivrus ot gniog saw buc siht fI
,hguoht gniripsni saw ecnedifnoc s'maiL
.flesmih rof ,yltsoM
.epac eulb sih fo redluohs eht no sraet sih gnipiw mih ees t’ndluoc netram enip eht erus ekam ot tseb sih gniyrt ,wap sih tcepsni madA tel tsuj eH
.nihc sih no gnippolp ykrej fo stib ,dias eh ",deksa uoY"
;siht rof tnaem t'ndah eH
.ylsuoituac tsirw sih ta gnillup yob flow egnarts siht saw ti ,oN
foohrednuhT,won dna ,elfir eht htiw kcapkcab sih pu gnikcip
.detsaot eb ydaerla d'yeht
.hguoht rettam t'ndiD  .eiL
.oga sedaced revo nworg neeb dah ti
ti ta dewehc dna ffo etib gib rehtona erot tsuj flow ehT
.reklatsthgiN a t'nsaw ti wenk netram enip ehT
,gniyas ,daeh sih koohs maiL
.eb ot evah t’ndid eh tub
"?gniod uoy er'tahW"
.slatem lufesu rof nwod deppirts eb ot tnemelttes ybraen eht otni deggul dah madA taht VT evissam a saw erehT
"?gniog uoy erehW"
,kcab gnimoc s'ti wonk I"
?gnihtyna gnirb uoy t'ndiD
.eniuneg saw ti ,tpels eh nehW
.tsehc evissam sti otni kcab knals daeh s'foohrednuht ehT
.dleif eht sdrawot tuo wap sih deggut ,rebmA ,gnilbis tsegnuoy siH
,daeh lufwa sti gnitfil saw ti sa tsuJ
"?og ot evah I od yhW"
;dad dna mom fo demaerd eH
.erehT"  .og tel neht dna
"?gniod uoy er'tahW"
.mih gnihctaw gnihtemos saw ereht wenk madA
.saw eh naht evarb ssel kool ot tnaw t'ndid osla eh tub
,edisni deppets maiL
.wap derujni sih htiw luferac ,oot esor flow ehT
.oga dnoces a gnilwoh neeb tsuj t’ndah eh ekil htuom sih ni ti deffuts dna
.foohrednuht eht ot kcab gninrut erofeb niaga mih gnihsuhs ,dnoces a rof daeh sih denrut madA
.ti fo diarfa t’nsaw eh
,dessih madA ",egaugnaL"
.buc eht morf ecniw a tog tI
.reveostahw nosaer on rof gnirednaw ,esoom elpmis a tsuj m'I
"?gnihtemos ro yttop uoy ekat ot deen I oD
:gnihtyna tih ot deganam tsrub dnuor-eerht eht fo eno ylnO
.part nimrev a fo swaj eht rednu ylthgit dehctans saw wap siH
.ti htaeneb nwod dekcud yehT
,levon a gnitirw si
hguoht taht laever ot tuoba t'nsaw eH
.gab eht gnisolc ,taht ta deffocs maiL
hcum oot truh tnemevom yna tub ,ylthgils ylno thguof buc ehT .mih sdrawot ti gnillup dna tsirw sih gnibbarg ,nwod dehcaer madA
.eson s'flow eht rednu pu regnif a kcuts netram enip ehT  ".daehbmuD"
.ti fo tsom eta uoY"
.gniraelc eht fo egde eht ot gnipeek ,netram enip eht tsap dehsup eh nehT
.sih saw tahw ekat dna emoc ot edistuo saw reveohw evird ylerus dluow stnuat siH
.mih dniheb tuhs rood eht demmals dna moor eht ot denrut eh ,taht htiw dnA
.liat s'netram enip eht gnibbarg ,derepsihw maiL ",yeH"
.tnetxe emos ot neppah ot ti dewolla d’eh dna
.yletaidemmi gnihtyna yas
"?nalc ruoy s'erehW"
"?gniod ew er'tahW"
",tsrif su dnif t'now ti ,ykcul er'ew fI
.teef sih ot pu gnitteg ,dias madA
"?uoy htiw peels I naC"
,regna ni yltsom ,kcab detuohs madA "!haeY"
.snroht dnasuoht a ekil tuo ni gnikcits sehcnarb dna nellaf lla sevael ,skcor eht tsgnoma eert enol a saw erehT
.ysaeuq mih gnikam
.ylduol ti gniwehc ,wam sih otni xim eht fo lufdnah a dellup maiL dna ,dias madA
.tekcop sih morf syek tuo gnillup ,dehgual madA
.seye daed sti ni regna na saw erehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.enips s’madA pu srevihs tnes meht fo lla dna ,seman tnereffid dnasuoht a dah tI
nug eht fo edis eht tsniaga wap tfel ruoy dloH"
,foohrednuht eht was meht fo enoN
"!lwwwwwwwwwoH"  !PANS  .kcip a ylno htiw rac a fo roterubrac eht tuo llup ot tuo mih dewohs ehs sa nwod dna pu daeh sih gniddon ,rehtom sih dniheb gnola dewollof eH
.doow fo lufecaf saw tog eh llA
.edis sih morf ssih duol a tog eh erofeb tsuj tohs eht ekat ot ydaer ,reggirt eht no saw regnif siH
"?doof ruoy fo tser eht s'erehW .yrgnuh llits m'I"
.sgnaf sti laever ot kcab gnillup elzzum
.nepo sdnilb eht evael ot erus saw eh
yhsub saw ruf rieht fo htoB
eerf flesmih dellup flow eht ,sregnif sih rof moor edam eh sa noos sA
.roolf delit eht tsniaga ylision deknulc dna yawa gnulf part eht litnu dnuora wap sih delggiw tsuj eH
,sretsis dna srehtorb elttil sih rof neve ton ,tfos eb t'ndluoc eH
.tops gnidih sih morf dellup eh ykrej fo kcits a gnigavar ,ereht llits saw yob ehT
,deksa dna sredluohs sih deggurhs madA
.ffo sregnif nwo sih raet saw od ot eganam thgim eh gniht ylno ehT
,dias yob eht ,doof fo lluf llits htuom sih htiW
.sretsis dna srehtorb elttil nezod flah a tog ev'I"
?od ot em tnaw uoy od tahW"
.nehctik eht ot kcab tog neht dna
,gniod saw eh tahw erus t'nsaw madA
.tsehc eht no flesmih deppat neht ,seye sih dellor netram enip ehT
.seye sih dellor netram enip eht dna ,denworf maiL
.tfel saw ecuas elttil tahw rof naelc depoocs sniamer ,tuo dellup neeb lla d'yehT
.em tuoba yrrow ot deen oN
.elbma sselerac sti ni seert eht morf ekorb foohrednuht ehT  .gnirevihs saw eH
,deddon flow ehT  .denraw madA
.kcab derepsihw eh ",hhhS"
,gnirettum ,ylthgils kcab depmuj maiL
",tub flesym ti od d'I
,daeh s'ti detfil ti nehT
,sruoh rof deklaw yehT
.emoh mih teg dna ylimaf sih buc siht dnif tsuj dluoc eh nehw
,pot no ti gniydaets ,detcurtsni sa did madA
.sreltna eht neewteb gnippiks nageb yticirtcele fo scrA
.raj eht denepo eh sa dias madA ",wap ruoy tuo dloH" .level s’flow eht ot nwod tog dna tnilps a dna
.mih morf saw netram enip eht raf woh gniciton ,kcab denrut maiL
",niaga ti evah reven ylbaborp ll'eW
,derepsihw maiL
,pmuj ot yob eht desuac tI
.delrans spil ,dias madA
.feilebsid ni daeh sih koohs madA
.thgif laer yna pu tup ot mih rof
.skeehc sih fo sedis eht nwod gninnur sraet ,mih ta pu dekool buc ehT
.deb fo tuo tog madA ,flesmih ot gnirettuM
dniw fo eltsur eht revo tub
.yaw elohw eht gnilbmert ,s’madA ni decalp saw wap dednuow siH
.hsuh a ot deppord sdrow sih dna ,dias eh
.kcab eht ot deit kcar
,ereht eb llits d'yeht fI
.yltcaf-fo-rettam os dias eh
.yenruoj rieht fo dne eht ta
.mih tcartsid ti tel t’ndid tub
.mih ot esolc teg ot gniyrt ,dias eh
.eurt t'nsaw taht wonk ot elzzum s'flow eht daer ot deen t'ndid madA  .eil rehtonA
.buc eht ot ti gnissot dna gab htolc a gnibbarg
t'ndid flow ehT  "?stnerap ruoy s'erehW"
.taht ta deffocs madA
.ti fo stol dna ,doof saw erehT
.kaeuqs a ni deksa maiL
.gol eht sdrawot mih gnigru ,ecap s'yob eht ta del gnieb won saw eH
.evah dluow mom sih ekil mih taws t'ndid tub
.esrow saw hcihw ediced ot gniyrt ,netram eht dna doolb eht ta gnicnalg ,dnoces a detatiseh eH
.edis s'flow eht ot gnihsur ,cinap ni tuo deirc madA ",taht potS"
.emit eht tsom ecnereffid eht llet t'nac sredart tub ,doog era meht fo lla toN"
,moor gnivil eht ni hcuoc eht ot yaw sih delbmuts dna ,esuoh eht ni spmal sag eht lla dellik madA
.ereht mih dehcuot eh netfo woh htiw deyonna gnitteg ydaerla saw eH
.moordeb eht sdrawot detrats dna rufdaeh sih delffur madA
.sregnif nekorb sih htiw gnihtyna barg ot ton luferac ,edisni dereep eH
,tsrif ta deneppah gnihtoN
,dias dna hcuoc eht ot detniop madA
.ria eht otni kcen gnol ylbissopmi sti dehcterts neht dna ria eht otni detfil daeh stI
.ti sserppus ot dluoc eh gnihtyreve did eh tub
.revoc fo tuo gnimoc ylwols ,detrats maiL
,thgin hcae htiw revarb gnitteg saw tI
,buc flow gnuoy a ,erehT
,dewac snevar nezod A
.dluoc eh sa drah sa pu dellup dna rab eht htaenrednu walc a dekooh eh tub
",kniht naht erom ti tnaw uoy sseuG"
.ti ot dnuora teg reve d'eh detbuod eh dna oga shtnom saw tahT
.tuo daeh sih dekop eh ,ylwolS
.gol a ot detniop flow ehT
,dehpmurrah flow ehT
.edisni dereep eh nehw tuo eugnot sih gnikcits dna gnirtsward eht dellup buc flow ehT
.htuom s'eramthgin citpylacopa-tsop eht fo tuo dehcterts seldeen dnasuoht A
.llah eht ot gnitniop
.kcab ti tup dna wam sih morf doof eht hctans ot gnitnaw
,madA no deniamer eralg sih dna gnitnap saw flow eht hguohT
.dnuos a ekam ot ton luferac ,sdoow eht otni tperc yehT
".daehbmud a er'uoY"
.yllaudividni meht kram ot sserp yek a dnif dna srood eht edoc roloc dluow eh taht aedi na saw erehT
taht ta decniw madA
”.deirrac eb ot dedeen reven ev’I"
.maiL ot dnuora gninnips ,delworg netram enip eht
,etoyoC triD yb ”thgilyaD eht fo sretsnoM“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.sdoow eht sdrawot ffo detniop elzzum sih erofeb ,seot sih fo spit eht ta doots eH
.dnuorg eht no toof sih depmots maiL
.erutaerc eht ta gnirats seye-ediw sih gniees ,buc eht ot denrut madA
.kcen sih gnikcarc dna sredluohs sih gnitator ,dias eh
",revo t'nsi sihT ?gniog I ma erehw naem uoy od tahW"
.sselwalf llits saw drocer kcart sih
.rekcusteet a ot resolc saw buc eht detcepsus won eh dna
.lluf ni tuo dednetxe seldeen fo slehsub esoht ,derab erew hteeT .skraps emas eht htiw gniwolg ydaerla sreltna ,tops eht morf deklaw tI
".oot daed lla er'yehT"
hguorht ,edistuO  etoyoC triD yB ”)2 fo 1 traP( thgilyaD eht fo sretsnoM“   yojne esaelP  .remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
.meht gniklats saw foohrednuht ehT
.kcen sih pans ot gnitiaw hcnarb a sa degalfuomac nwod edispu gnidih ,retnuhdaeH a t'nsaw tI
.ssenisub sti saw gnihton ekil gnola gnisom ,dimit demees tI
?dik siht saw kcuf eht ohw tsuJ
",kert syad owT"
.sgnik ekil eta madA dna maiL
.dekcol llits saw ti fi ees ot eldnah eht detset eh sa dias eh
,niaga dias eh dna kcab tnew srae s'maiL
.erofeb deciton t'ndah eh evorg a gnileef ,hguoht dlot saw eh sa did eH
.desuac dah eh noitcurtsed eht was madA taht neht ylno saw tI
.mih gnikaw tuohtiw doof emos neddih dah nmadA erehw draob neddih eht nepo pir ot deganam dah yob ehT
",nwo ym no ereh kcab gnihtyreve gniyrrac ton m’I esuaceB"
.flesmih rof demialc dah eh taht snoitacol tnereffid rof lla
,detrats madA ",siht tuoba woh
",erons t'nod I"  .eiL
.esir elkcah s'madA edam tahT
".esoht rof tuo eye na peek attog tsuj ew os ,neewteb ni srekram wef a s'erehT
"?sseug I ,flesruoy pleh 'nippilf tsuJ"
".tey steknalb artxe eht dedart ev'I kniht t'nod I dna sdeb owt sah esuoh sihT"
.detiaw eH  "!tuo emoc dias I"
.gniraelc s'nibac eht fo tuo del taht htap on saw erehT
.ffo ti llup ot gniyrt
.deviecer eh eralg prahs eht gniciton ,dias eh
,ecaf evarb a no tup
”,eiL“  ".daed er'yehT"
.yticirtcele tuohtiw nur ot edam saw nibac eht tub
.ydaer elfir ,ni emoc ll'I dna tuo llac tsuj ,yracs gnihtyna ees uoy fI
.esoom laref a eb ot deraeppa tahw saw sgel evissam ruof no gniklaW
.mih thguac dah ti erehw ruf eht ykcits ot gninnigeb saw doolb dna yldrawkwa tneb erew htoB
.meht dniheb dih dna seert dnuof htoB
.tnelis eb ot mih rof regnif a pu dleh flow eht tub
.htaenrednu dekcut flesmih gnipeek tub
"?erofeb nug a desu reven uoy evaH
.gol eht ot pu ti gnirb ot mih rof denoitom dna elfir eht ta detniop eh nehT ".uoy
.eracs elttil a redurtni eht evig tsuj dluow ti thguoht
.niaga lufhsab gnikool flow eht was ,denrut madA
.sdoow eht fo revoc eht ot tnirps lluf a otni ffo gnikat erofeb ,yldliw ria eht otni gnicnarp ,pu tohs foohrednuht ehT  !kcarC !kcarC !kcarC
.tsugsid ni detsiwt elzzum s’madA  ".maiL"
".moor rehto eht ni eb ll'I
.enif eb ll'uoY"
.dnaletsaw siht gnitagivan trams erew elpoep tub
.revo lla mih delkcit dna ruf sih deltsirb taht kcohs elttil a tnes ti
!elpoep ta taht tniop t'noD"
.buc eht ot dnuora kcab gnippilf ,denaorg eH
.knis nehctik eht htaenrednu hsats neddih ym sdnif eno on epoh erus I .thgirla ,lleW"
.gnitadimitni dekool eh depoh dah tub
,taorht sih ni deraor lwoh A .desolc elzzum sih htiw delworg eH
.nibac dnoces a ot rood eht dehcaorppa yeht sa
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.reggirt eht dezeeuqs dna
.nehctik sih morf deraor eciov A
,net naht erom on
.kcab gninrut neve ton ,dias madA
.tnatsni na ni kcab depmuj maiL tub ,swap s'buc eht fo tuo thgir gab eht hctans ot edam madA  "?ti s'tahT"
",ton yletulosbA" .hgual a fo krab a tuo tel madA
,ylprahs dias eh nehT
,hguoht ylgnittiwnU
.oga dnoces a dah eh naht retteb ylthgils tlef eh dna
.seye s'buc eht otni dekool eh dna
,foohrednuhT a s'tI"
"!tohs ym ssim em edam uoY"
.ecnahc eht tog reven tI
.niaga tae reve dluoc I kniht t'nod I" ,tuo dehgis maiL
.gniklaw tpek eh tub ,dednuofbmud ,daeh sih denrut flow ehT
,rotca tseb eht t’nsaw eh ,ylgnittimdA
.gnihton otni gnilias tnew owt rehto ehT .eert eht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
,pu srae sih gnikreP
,flesmih ot reyarp a dias
.potretnuoc a otno tik eht gnimmals ,seye sih dellor madA  .ylision
.hgis a ni elzzum sih morf dedurtorp ria fo elahxe elbisiv A
.tarb a ekil hcum siht gnitca saw eh fi ega s'yob eht degdujsim yllaer d'eH
?tnaw uoy ti si tahW"
.tnilps nedoow eht dna segadnab eht debbarg madA
.eert eht dniheb llits
,tohs doog a t'nsaw eH
,hcnip llams a ,walc sih no deggans tI
dnuorg eht ot nellaf d’taht ykrej fo eceip eht deggans eh
,delworg dna flesmih sdrawot kcab mra sih werd neht ,deknilb madA
.sdracsid ralimis dnif d'eh
.psag a htiw ekowa eh nehw mra sih no gniggut t’nsaw rebmA
,ecnis gninrom yrevE
",raiL"  ".yna evah t'noD"
.ronoh sih gnidnefed saw eh ekil
.mih fo tnorf ni yltcerid tuo gab eht dah llits maiL deciton eh
,ecnayonna ni delworg madA
.tsaeb eht ffo seye sih gnikat ton ,derepsihw maiL ",thgit ti peeK .redluohs ruoy otni nug eht fo kcab eht –kcots eht hsuP"
esu yllaer dluoc eh tahW
"?kcab gnimoc s'ti kniht uoY"
,deppots gninthgil eht ,nehT
",truh ylbaborp ll'sihT"
,deksa maiL ,sroolf doowdrah eht otni toof sih gnihctarcS
.deb sih ot txen dnatsthgin a ot revo dehcaer daetsni madA
,deb ot flesmih tas eh nehT
,meht fo nezod elpuoc a dah eH
.gnola gniwollof ,maiL htiw yawrood eht hguorht deklaw dna denway eh nehT ".dnuora
.flesmih htaenrednu elfir eht gnidih
.dnuorg eht no sdrib daed eht ot delbma tI
.rab eht deppord madA dna
..remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer
.ylkciuq dednopser madA
.wap sih fo kcab eht htiw ti fo edis eht dettab neht dna ,noitcerid slerrab eht morf yaw eht fo tuo dekcud flow ehT
.gnihctiwt llits ,nevar a revo wam sti denepo ti ,nwod gnihcaeR
.wap derujni sih htiw yltfos ylleb nellows sih dettap eH ".niaga
.eson sih gnilknirw dna ffins a gnikat
".eno eht tog ylno I esuac teknalb nwo ruoy thguorb uoy epoH
.laem taht rebmemer retteb uoY"
",em htiw gnimoc er'uoy worromot snaem tI"  .denihw eh
.daehbmud a em llac t'noD"
.setadpu erutuf rof
.sevil rieht htiw depacse flah rehto ehT
.yek thgir eht dnif ot deganam eh emit eht yb enog dna emoc dah thgiliwt ehT  .saw tI
.stnecs rieht dna dniw eht ni gnikat ,deralf slirtson evissam owT
.detnaw eh woh gab eht gnidloh saw eh litnu flow eht gnitsujda ,dnuora nups netram enip ehT  .eiL
.su kcart dna yrt ti tel ot suoregnad oot s'tI
detanimon saw ”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“ ,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
".gniyl er'uoy nehw llet nac I
.thgin tsal morf sehtolc emas eht ni llits saw netram enip ehT
.ecno elbat eeffoc eht otni gnikconk ylno
.ot dah eh naht rehtruf pu og t'ndid eh dna ,kcab dedlof erew srae siH
".won owt rof deef ot evah annog m'I ecnis yllaicepsE
.fo dir teg ot drah erew snalC
.dedaol ylluf saw ti gniees ,elfir sih morf enizagam eht ffo dellup eH
!thgir ,haeY" .elzzum elttil bmud sih ot thgiarts dehgual eH
,hguone saw taht ekil kool t'ndid maiL
",daeh sti ta thgir detniop s'ti taht os
.flesmih ot thguoht madA
eht fo eno ylbaborp
".won yb tnenitnoc eht fo edis rehto eht no ylbaborp si gniht tahT ?revo
.redluohs ruoy revo ti worhT"
.tnemtnio fo raj a gnidnif erofeb ssem eht hguorht gnigammur ,esac eht pu denepo eH
.diletsum eht morf elims naem a tog taht dna
.sdoow eseht ni seiddab tseggib
.kaolc eulb s'flow eht ot detniop neht eH
,puorg a etamiced dluoc diar tidnab a ro
,gnineve taht reilrae nehctik sih fo sllaw eht ni draob a dniheb doof sih yawa tup eh nehW
,elzzum s'maiL revo dekoorc elims naem yttons A
"?…ro esoht fo eno kaerb ot em tnaw uoy oD"
,sroloc eht dezingocer eh thguoht madA
.gnilbmert sdrow ,deksa madA
,tuo dellac dna sdoow eht ot kcab sih denrut eh
,dekrow ti taht ngis doog a ylbaborp ,slirtson sih gnuts tI
,gnihtyna yas dluoc eh erofeB
redluohs sih otni thgir deppils tI
.od mih dah evah dluow mom sih tahw s'tahT
.sregnif nekorb sih pu dloh ot desuap eh
.mih fo tnorf ni gab a gnidloh ,dniheb dewollof buc flow ehT
.gniliocnu ekans a ekil sehcnarb eht fo esab eht ot pu ydob sti fo tuo derehtils tI
".won deb ot og ot gniog m'I
.seye sih dellor flow eht dna ,deksa madA
.swap sih no buc derujni na dah eh woN
,emoh ta ti fo esu emos ekam dluoc eh ,eruS
.eldnah eht llup t'noD .reggirt eht ezeeuqs dna htaerb ruoy dloH"
,deilper ,elims hsipmi na kcab gnidloh ton ,madA
.detsat reve d'yeht retaw tsedloc eht htiw selzzum rieht dellif yeht ,revir a tA
.riafnu saw ti dna
.thgit ti dloh dna
.nehctik eht fo emarfrood eht hguorht delbmuts eh sa sesruc gnirettum ,erom ecno elbat eeffoc eht otni dekconk eH
",morf emac tsuj ew erehw ot ti miA
.tluda na ot ekops eh taht yaw eht draeh d'ehs fi rae sih fo pit eht ffo deppin evah erus d'ehs ,ereh saw moM fI
,sdnaletsaw deyortsed raw eht ni enola gnivil otni hserf raey a ylno saw eh hguohT
.emit dnoces a evom t’ndid eh
.yaw eht mih gniwohs ,sregnif nekorb sih htiw detniop maiL
,retniw eht ni yllaicepse ,kciht saw ruf s'flow A .delbmurg madA
.gninthgiL dehcnuH ehT
.yrujni eht tcepsni ot eson sih sdrawot ti dellup dna tsirw sih yb flow eht debbarg eh nehT
.dloc s'retniw eht yb devreserp dna delaes ,eert a ni ti fo tsom pu deit d'eH
.mih rof llaw eht edisni tfel netram enip eht esirprus eht gnitapicitna t'nsaw tub
.ta kcep ot srettirc nezorf yna rof dekool yeht sa dnuora gnippoh
,tol a htrow erew sreltna esohT
.sreksihw rieht morf gnilgnad selcici llams tfel tI
.sgge fo snotrac owt saw stroffe sih rof tog eh llA
dna rood tnorf eht ta dewalc tsuj evah dluow taht ekil retsnom A
.swap sih pu dleh madA  ”?tahW“
"?rehtegot tpels ew fi won thgirla eb ti dluoW"
.ti ot noitnetta gniward tuohtiw ecaf sih gninaelc deirt yob eht ,niagA
.eert eht fo esab eht ta deppots foohdnuht ehT
.dnim sih ni hserf llits liocer eht ,gnuts pih sih ni sseneros ehT
.yad eht tuohguorht stnemevom sih gnikcart dna ,yrgnuh ,evila saw edistuo gniht sihT
.pot no gnuls elfir ,wot ni kcapkcab htiw esuoh eht fo tuo gniklaw ,dias madA
.sehcnarb eht morf deppord snevar nezod a flah a dna
,ecnelis ni ereht tas yehT  ..flow eht morf ssorca dnalsi nehctik a tsniaga kcab sih htiw raer sih otno gnillaf ,dias madA ",og ot dooG
.hctiwt ot nageb srae sti ,skcor eht ssorca morf ees dluoc eH
.rehto hcae ot txen thgir era smoordeb ehT"
.morf emac eh erehw ot kcab buc flow siht teg ot dah madA
,part eht ta debbarg flow eht ,detartsurF
.sdoow eht hguorht dehcram yeht nehT
.esolc oot dehcrep snevar fo puorg a hguorht neewteb gnicar cra na ,sreltna s'foohrednuht eht fo tuo deppaz gninthgiL
"?naem ot desoppus taht s'tahW"
,retniw fo daed eht ni seert sselfael eht hguorhT
.nrohezuF .eramthgiN s’alseT
.redluohs sih revo elfir ,rood neercs tnorf eht hguorht gnippets ,deirc madA "!tuo emoC"
.ssenkrad eht hguorht gnireep seye esnes dluoc eh
,gnaf a neewteb tuo taem foohrednuht fo revils rehtona teg ot deganam eh emit yrevE
.flesmih no ni knurhs maiL litnu buc eht revo llat gnidnats ,delworg madA
.elzzum sih ot deppals tnemelzzup fo tib a ,mih fo tnorf ni buc eht ta drah detniuqs madA
"?tahW" ,tuo delworg eh dna kcab tnew srae s'maiL
"?mraw gnipeek neeb uoy ev'woH
.gnola denetsil madA dna ,thgir dna tfel decnad selgnairt egral s'flow ehT
.mraf eht fo demaerd eh ,deb sih nI
,hteet sih neewteb llits ykrej eht htiw dias dna
"?uoy eracs foohrednuht gib eht diD ?tahW
elzzum sih ni ykrej eht deffuts yob ehT
.wap derujninu sih tuo dleh neht dna
,dias madA ",kcul ni er'uoY"
.dnuora gnikcits eb annog er'uoy fi sgniht od ot uoy tcepxe I"
,revoc fo tuo teg ot tnaw t'ndid eH
.seert eht revo detniop dna deddon madA ,llitS
,yllacinhcet os ,stsaeb dliw ffo eracs dna selttob nekorb ssim ot ti gnisu yltsom saw ecneirepxe siH
drah saw dlrow nrot raw sihT
.sretsis dna srehtorb sih fo demaerd
.wap sih yb mih barg ot dnuora nups eh dna ,dedlof srae siH
.niaga ksa ot detnaw eh llet dluoc eH
.reggirt eht dellup dna ,flesmih decarb netram enip eht
.seilppus rof tnemelttes a otni nur ot deen I"
.ylreporp regnarts a ot flesmih ecudortni t'ndid eh fi mih dlocs dluow mom siH .srennam sih
.hcnurc ytsan a evag dna ,elzzum sti otni naiva eritne eht depruls ti ,kcus gninekcis a htiW
.pu nehguot ot evah dluow eh
.daeh sih koohs dna dehgis maiL
,selbmurg fo wohs a no gnittuP
.ruf sih fo ffo dloc eht gnikahs
",enola ton tub ,ereh yats ot eerf er'uoY"
.peels emos teg tsuJ
.yawllah eht ni tesolc seilppus eht ot deklaw dna teef sih ot tog madA
”thgilyaD eht fo sretsnoM“
.dnopser t'ndid flow ehT
"?suoires eb t'nac uoY"
.yas ot eganam dluoc eh lla saw tahT ".eldnah
,tnemtnio eht fo tnuoma llams a pu depoocs netram enip ehT
.pirg htaed a ni sehcnarb eht otni dekooh snolat rieht dna ,elgaedaerps tnew sgniw riehT .nrocpop ekil meht fo ffo gnidolpxe srehtaef ,delzzis yehT
,hcamots s’madA morf pu delbbub tliug A
.swap sih otni dna gnils eht fo ffo ti gnippils ,elfir sih debbarg eH
".dloc tsuj s'tI !oN"
,won yerp eht erew yeht fI
.flesmih esopmoc ot etunim a gnideen flow eht
.niaga kaeps flow eht did derevoc erew yeht nehw ylnO
.gut prahs a liat sih evig ot teknalb eht htaenrednu wap a gnihcaer
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
".derit er'uoy fi uoy yrrac annog ton m'I dna pots tsrif ruo erofeb syaw gnol a s'tI
t'nsi sihT" .edis s'flow eht gnippat ,pu thguac madA
.taht no gniyler ylno drah neeb ev'tsum ti tub
.pih sih ta elfir eht dleh dna rebmahc eht dedaol eh
.dnuos gnimmuh emas taht tuo ekam dluoc yeht
.dekcolnu hctal eht evael ot erus edam eh ,rood eht desolc eh nehW
.mih gniwollof eb ot desoppus saw eh dezilaer eh erofeb dnoces a gnikat ,detlit daeh s'madA
.maiL morf yawa flesmih gninrut erofeb seye sih gnibbur ,delbmurg madA
.eerf meht pir ot gniyrt ,esab nedoow sti ta deggut yob ehT
.eraw gnikooc leets sselniats fo tes wen hserf a saw
,dehsinif maiL ,hteet derettahc htiW
.deracs dna ,flesti no ni delruc
,dias eh ",madA m'I"
.derewsna sekalfwons fo llaf tfos eht ylnO
".teknalb oN .seriF .sevaC"
.seert eht ot yaw sti gnilbma llits
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.mih gnicaf wodniw eht morf gnimoc thgilnus fo gnipleh doog a tog eh ,niaga seye sih denepo madA nehW
,noisufnoc llams htiw epac sih ta dekool maiL
.ees ot tuoba saw eh tahw wenk flow siht detcepsus eh ,llew sA
.netram eht dniheb gnola gniwollof ,deksa buc ehT
.htgnel ni gjiworg kcen
"?wonk uoy ,thgir uoy sevreS"
.eromyna egrahc ni eno eht saw eh ekil leef t'ndid eh dna
pu ti eniL .thgis ruoy si elfir eht fo pot nO"  .ylthgils ylnO
,niaga detuohs eh ,emac gnihton nehW
,niaga dias dna eugnot sih tuo kcuts maiL
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,llams gnihtemos mih wohs ot detnaw ehS
".bmud fo lluf s'daeh ruoy snaem tI" ,derewsna eh dna
.thgis s'elfir eht otni yltcerid daeherof nwo sti enil ot deganam dah ti
.hguorht gnikaerb elffins lanoitnetninu na ,dedlof srae s'flow ehT
.reduol gniworg gnimmuh eht ,wolg ot nageb kcar sti fo spit ehT
".denaelc eb ot deen annog s'taht tub ,uoy no gnihtyna etsaw t'ndluohs I"
,derettum eh dna roolf eht ot deppid elzzum s’maiL
",seilppus gnitteg er'ew yhw s'tahT
.doolb eht ,yltnerappA
.flesmih rof tuo koot eh ,rehtonA
.tsaeb laref ro erutaerc citpylacopa-tsop rehto yna ro rennikstuonS a ro revaerdoolB a t’nsaw tI
epat emos tuo koot eh nehT
.enob yb enob tuo dellup saw thgin tsal netae d'eh lwof ehT
.1202 fo yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof
.erutinruf eht tsuj ot nwod deppirts neeb dah ecalp ehT
,knis eht htaenrednu part eht rof llaf t'ndid eH
meht morf seil tahw dna
.ssenerus ni yllaer ton dna
.gnol siht devivrus eh dna dloc taht t'nsaw nibac eht ,llitS
.dehca pih s'madA
.ti ni ytip fles dna regna htob dleh ezag siH
.gniraelc ykcor a emac seert eht hguorhT
,snetram naht reggib erew sevloW
,saw hguoht yas dluoc eh llA
".thgin lla pu em tpek gnirons ruoY"
,neeb dah ereht fI
.oga snosaes wef a esproc a morf elfir eht pu dekcip dah eH
.erofeb deciton t’ndah eh gnimmuh a saw erehT .denetsil eh
.swap sih neewteb elfir eht ,tnatsni na ni pu saw madA
.htolc eht ni pu meht depparw neht dna sregnif sih tes eH
.tuo derettum maiL ",mu ,yeH"
.ti morf seye rieht dleihs ot erus eb d'eh ,retsis ro rehtorb regnuoy sih saw ti fI
".neve lla s'ti os ,syawyna em trohs yehT
.su sllik ti erofeb ti llik annog er'eW"
.daeh sih don saw od dluoc eh lla tub
.doow eht hguorht tlem ot dica evitcaoidar pu deweps
.lworg yrgnuh lufitip a evag flow eht sa ylduol dehgual eH
.moor gnivil eht ot gninrut ,dias eh
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,kciuq dias eh ",yttop t'nod I"
.keew eht ni reilrae egabrag sih tuo werht eh nehw
,rof stlob dna stun leets fo sdnuop ytrof dedart eh derebmemer yltcnitsid eh eno ,tik ycnegreme na tuo dehsif eH
.seert eht dniheb tsuj gnipeek llits ,gnola degdurt flow eht ,gninrut tuohtiW
",siht ta doog yllaer er'uoy ekil dnuos t'nseod tI"
.dnuow eht revo lla tnemtnio eht deraems eh
",daehbmud a ton m'I"
,taht htiW  ".haey ,adniK"
,yrevarb sih gnivorp fi sA
,demaercs dna yawa dehcoocs yob ehT
,su fo deracs ton s'tI
.yawa daeh sih dekcud eh dna dedlof srae s'buc ehT
,tserof eht fo kcalb eht otni ,wodniw eht
.gninaem dah ti taht dnatsrednu t’ndid eh fi sa
.tniopkcehc tsrif eht dehcaorppa yeht emit eht yb hteet sih ta gnikcip llits saw netram enip ehT
.weiv otni emac yllaudarg sreltna eht ,hguone erus dnA
"!parC !eiwo ,eiwo ,eiwO"
,dam eb annog s'ti dna
.ekahs a ti gnivig dna nug eht gnibbarg yb trap tsal taht dehsinif eH ".ydaer
"?gniog er'ew erehw wonk neve uoy oD"
.tarb elttil a htiw gniugra naht retteb saw eH
,htaerb a ni koot madA
rehtegot lla ti deit netram eht sa lwoh gib tsal eno saw erehT
.rab llik eht yb drah nwod depmalc erew sregnif s'flow eht fo owT
.deggurhs tsuj madA  .mih dekcom eh
.raeppasid dluoc nalc eritne na yaw on saw ereht neht ,enoyreve etanimile t'ndluoc sbmob eht fI
.shtnom rof rotareneg a ekil gnitca fo elbapac
.liat sih ffo wap s'buc eht gnittaws ,deppots madA
.retal etarenicni ot edisni deffuts d'eh erus saw eh snaeb fo snac erew erehT
.dnuora elfir eht gnivaw ,delworg netram enip eht "!eiwo ,thgir nmaD"
.esab eht morf raf oot t'nsi tnemelttes ehT .ereht revo sniatnuoM"
.ti deltrats ylno uoY
.derepsihw maiL ",foohrednuhT"
".ffo dessip dna yrgnuh llits ylbaborp s'ti dna
.smra sih dedlof flow ehT
.gnihctaw morf flesmih peek t'ndluoc eh tub
.dekil evah dluow eh naht retsaf emoc dah gninroM
.tniopkcehc eht ot eunitnoc dna ,kcab og tsuj rehtar hcum d'eh
".yzarc oG .stun dna stiurf deirD"
,emoh maiL ekat ot seunitnoc madA woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
ti ni meht fo tol a htiw espalloc dluoc gnidliub a ,eruS
.uoy eb ot evah annog s'tI"
"?eseht era tahW"
.kcirt a tsuj saw ti wenk eH
,gnihtemos od llits dluohs eh ekil tlef eh hguoht dna ,t'nsaw eH
.ereht peels nac uoY"
,nepo reward a dellup eH
,fmmH"   .erab ot drah erew seye yppup esoht ,llitS
.yrc gninraw a ekam ot gninepo kaeb ,dnuora nups drib A
,dessih eh ",taht gniod kciuQ"
.oga setunim tsuj gnidnats erew yeht erehw seert eht gniees ,dlot saw eh sa did madA
.tsehc sih ot gnillaf ti fo flah ,deppans ti taht ykrej eht no drah os nwod tib flow ehT
,ruf sih dettam dah tnemtnio eht nehW
,gol eht sdrawot devruc daeh s'foohrednuht ehT
.rof mih hsinup dluow mom sih gniht rehtona ,dias eh
",muihtiL .seirettaB"
"?uoy t'ndluow ,taht ekil d'uoY"
.flow yttarb emos rof ton yllaicepse dna
ti deciton tsrif d’eH
,noitnetta gniyap saw flow eht fi ees ot dnuora denrut eh nehW
,yllaer epoh a ,thguoht a saw erehT
",pleh em tel tsuJ .dik ,toohS"
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.stser kciuq rof gnippots ylno
.kcab tog eh nehw ereht eb ton thgim yob eht taht
.edih ot ecalp wen a dnif ot deen ew os
.dnoces a rof rood eht ta doots dna dewollof flow ehT
.tuo deplug flow eht