.pihsnoitaler rieht yned ot nika oot
won thgir ereh t'nsaw mom tuB
,nepo gnuh wam siH
.tuo detrulb madA ",oN"
wap dab sih htiw gnihcaer yltnedicca ,gab eht rof delbmuf flow ehT
,yltnatsni esool emac tI
".segdir tog neve s'ti ,kooL
,wap derujni sih htiw mih dellup flow ehT
,dad dna mom sih ees t'ndluoc eH
.desufnoc derats buc eht
.psarg etiuq t'ndluoc madA taht mih ot ssenisword a saw erehT
.meht fo os ro nezod a ebyam saw erehT
.tnemeerga ni deddon dna ti koot ehS
.nirg a kcab dloh ot elbanu elihw
.repap fo teehs a ta nwod dekool ehs sa deksa retto yltrop a ",emaN"
.maiL ot revo eno dekcuhc eH
.dniheb llaf maiL gnittel
.regnevacs a m'I esuaceB"
,deksa maiL "?tah a s'tahT"
.daeh sih koohs madA
,tnemevom elgnis a ni detlah s'flow os ro nezod llA
,detaeper eh ,bos a nI
.psag a ni deksa eh "?yllaeR"
.maiL ecaf ot denrut eh dna
,gniyas erofeb dnuora meht delggij eH
saw erehT .dnuora dekool dna ,deppots madA
.gninepo eht ot daeh sih gninrut ,dias eh
,deddon dna dehgis madA
,mih morf tsehtruf tops eht koot maiL
.emit eht eraps dluoc eh mih dlot dnim sih fo kcab eht ni gnihtemos tub ,emoh maiL teg rehtar hcum d'eh dna
"?dneirflrig a tuoba tahW"
,dehsinif ehs dna ,dexaler yehT
.elbat eht no nep reh gnippat emit siht ,detaeper ehs ",emaN"
,moor elttil yknid a saw tI
.yas mih tel reven dluow mom sih taht sdrow
,esle enoemos morf epip a yb nepo degdew neeb d'tI
.hcum gnivom morf mih gnipeek dna ylthgit mih gnidloh ,maiL dnuora flesmih depparw madA .ecno ta lla tuo
mih ta dekool ahpla eht ylnO .meht ton tub
,dias maiL ",ttub ruoy was I"
.kcab mih gniggut ,mra s'madA debbarg wap A
.foohrednuhT yrgna na fo htarw eht epacse ylerab ot deganam tsuj dah maiL dna madA ,emit tsaL
"?ereh ni teg neve uoy d'nehW"
.emit eritne eht gnizigolopa maiL
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.ylppus trohs ni t'nerew skcapkcaB
.ecaf sih ni sregnif nekorb sih devaw eh sa neve ,buc eht erongi ot gniyrt ,drawrof seye sih dah eH
.drawrof mih derehsu eh ,wap sih fo evaw eht htiW
",resolc yna semoc ti fI"
.pu dedraob ro tuhs delaes t'nsaw taht ecnartne suoivbo on saw ereht ,erofeb ekil tuB
.epip eht ta dehsab dna drawrof toof sih degnul eh ,htgnerts sih lla htiW
.sgnaf dna swalc sih htiw doog ytterp mih nettog dah maiL ,llew sA
.mals duol a htiw tuhs delaes gninepo s'toohs eht dna
,hcuoc eht ot txen elbat dne na ot dehcaer madA
.dehsuh sdrow ,tuo deplug eh
.daor tlahpsla nrot a tem yeht sa tsuj
.dnim sih no stop eht denoitnem reven madA  .eiL
,kool lacizziuq a mih evag flow eht nehw dna
.sretsis dna srehtorb sih fo t'nsaw ti
".gnihtemos draug dna ta doog er'uoy gniht eno eht od uoy t'nod yhw os ,draug a er'uoY"
.spil sih derekcup dna yllufyalp flow eht devohs madA  "?dneirf...yoB"
.htaerb sih hctac ot deirt eh sa tuo gnignah eugnot
.llaw nwod nrot eht fo elbbur eht no gnittis meht fo owt eht ,dias maiL
.rorrim ynnuf a otni gnicnalg lla erew yeht ekil
.yzah elttil a eciov ,dias eh
,detaeper dna ylmrif pu dekool eh neht dna
,niaga ,esuoh eht tfel yehT
.ruf floW .ti ees dluoc eh
,spih sih delggaw eH
.kcab deil eh ",enif s'tI"
.erom detnaw buc eht tub
,detsiwt selzzum riehT
.mih deppots madA tub ,kcab ezag sih nrut ot dekool maiL
.hsiloof os gnieb rof mih evigrof reven dluow mom sih dna elbisnopser eb ylerus d'eH
.tserof eht hguorht dedeecorp yeht
.secaf evissimsid dna selims dekciw erow srehtO
.nihc sih gnihcuot regnif a
.yrros m'I .maiL ,oN"
.stegdag dna ,seilppus ,doof htiw shtoob fo wor a gniciton ,deksa
,siht ekil t'ndid netram enip ehT
".ti htrow s'ti yllufepoh os ,evivrus ot nac ew tahw od eW
,ecap sih pu dekcip eh os
,dias dna nwod flesmih elttes ot wap a devaw netram enip ehT
",tluaf ym s'taht dna ereht ni og uoy tel I
tnemesab eht otni peed gniylf
,wodniw eht hguorht gnipeerc nus gnisir eht fo thgil eht hguorhT
,deerga eh sa nevE
.redluob eht revo tsuj gnihtemos was eh sa pu krep srae s'flow eht
flesmih rof erom saw siht taht dezilaer eh taht won ylno saw tI
,deksa eh ,buc eht ot eno dessap eh sA
.netram enip eht morf epiws a degdod dna ,delggig maiL
",enif eb ll'tI" ,derepsihw eH
.dnuorg eht ot nwod yllacitcarp saw ti litnu stnap sih fo kcab eht gnippord ,revo tneb dna dnuora gnuws netram enip ehT
.tuo teg dluoc drow a erofeb ffo mih tuc ehs tub ,gninepo wam sih
.nuf elttil a neeb dah maiL htiw emit gnidneps dna
,deksa eh dna netram eht ot tnew seye siH
.tnemelttes eht fo edisni eht sdrawot gnikool ,dias eh ",madA"
.mih ta waj sih deppans dna ,delrans maiL
.eil egnarts a saw tI  .eiL  ".oN"
.tnecs s'rehtaf sih ffins ot nwod elzzum sih dehcaer madA
.ni evid ot ydaer gnikool ,dias eh
.trihs sih ta erot swalc sih dna mra sih otni knus sgnaf s'flow ehT
.drawrof mih llup ot gniyrt dna maiL gnibbarg ,kcab dehcaer eH
.tnemelttes eht edisni tpels yeht ,thgin tahT
.htrof dna kcab koohs daeh siH  "?ereht nwod enoyna ereht saW"
.piy prahs a emac ereht
.tcepsni ot revo ti gnirb dna
dna ereht peels nac uoY"
.roolf eht otno kcapkcab eht gnippord ,dehgis madA
.llaw edis a hguorht nrot dah kao nellaf a tub
,meht dniheb sniatnuom
,ni meht derehsu ognid A
.ni tog elpoep thgir eht ylno erus edam ohw ,ycuL dna
?elas rof evah yeht snap ynam woh em llet uoy naC"
"?tuo em gniksa uoY ?yhW"
,enod lla saw ti nehW
.tnemelttes eht dna meht neewteb tops efas rehtona dah eh ,ylikcuL
”)2 fo 2 traP( thgilyaD eht fo sretsnoM“   yojne esaelP
".stun dna stiurf deirD .oN"
".yob a tsuj s'eH .dloc er'uoY"
.ti ekil ot gniog t'nsaw eh wenk eh
".sedih eht rof kooL
.flah ni madA dekcarc tI
.buc eht fo ffo eye sih gnikat ton ,gab sih hguorht degammur madA
strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,gninrom eht ni tfel yeht nehW  .maiL saw
.morf gnimoc saw thguoht taht erehw erus t'nsaw eH
.remrahC eniuqE eht
.emit eritne eht dehgual yehT
,tnatculer saw maiL
.niaga kool dluohs eW"
sedih eht gniyrrac trac a ot dekloy neeb dah tsaeb fo rennam emoS
.nwod lwarc ot ysae eb dluow ti erehw ees dluoc madA dna detniop eH
.yltrohs dne na ot emoc ot tuoba lla saw ti tub
"?yug taht ees uoY ?maiL ,yeH"
".gnol ereh eb t'now I .ni dengis teG"
,rehtegot deb eht no tpels yeht
.flesmih ot ylthgit dehctulc kcapkcab ,doots tsuj eH
"?ereht nwod ees uoy did tahW"
elzzum sih fo edis eht pu depeerc elims yls A  ".tsafkaerb
".tihs peed ni eb ll'ew ,tuo kcab teg t'nac uoy fi ro kcuts teg uoy fI"
"?secalp ruoy fo eno taht sI"
.htnom tsal dehsaw eseht tog tsuj I"
.flow eht rof saw ti naht
.hgU  " tsaf yllaer peels ot tnew uoY
.kcab s'maiL ot wap a tup dna tleb sih delkcub eh ,ylkciuQ
.mih ta pu deralg dna nep reh nwod tup ehs ,kcawht a htiW
.og tel ot diarfa oot ,ylthgit mih decarb flow eht tub
.ylimaf sih ot kcab mih teg ot gniyrt tsuj m'I
.riafnu saw siht tub ,drah saw dlrow nrot raw sihT
.srae s'maiL neewteb thgir ti gnittup yb dehsinif eh ",tah laiceps" —deraeb sgnaf
".em fo tuo tihs eht deracs uoY .maiL ,suseJ"
.ffo dekcab eh ,worruf sworb s'retto eht gnieeS ".ylimaf
",thgirla eb annog s'tI
.snosaer sih yfitsuj ot deen t'ndid eH
,mih dehsuhs madA "!ehtaerb t'nac I"
.sredluohs sih no swap sih gnittup
,ecaps nwo sih ekil did eh sa hcum sA
,mih fo daeha spets elpuoc a saw maiL sa noos sA
.wen gnihton tub
,mih ni gniworg ecneitapmi na saw erehT
.flesym ot ecaps emos dedeen tsuj I dna
.maiL ta nwod gnikool ,daeh sih denrut eH
.hguone noos emoh gnidaeh eb d'yehT
,deunitnoc ehs erofeb semit lareves ksed eht tsniaga depparw wap reH
?moordeb rehto ehT"
,daeh sih koohs netram enip ehT
.llew sa gnilims flow eht
.neeb dah siht naht tnasaelp ssel neve ylbaborp dna
.kcab tog eh nehw ereht t'nsaw maiL fi smelborp eb d'ereht desimorp taht taerht a
.buc tsol a s'eH" ,delworg madA
".gnihtyreve tog ev'yehT
",ffuts doog eht teg ot redro ni raf og ot deen uoY
.noitnetta rieht gnitteg emit siht ,niaga dellac madA
.thgir dna tfel gnitfihs elzzum ,swap reh daerps ehS
.thgirla s'tI .uoy tog I"  ".ehtaerb t'nac I"
".teg dluoc ew tahw enigamI
.flow eht deromuh eh tub
.1202 fo
,maiL dniheb tog eh sa
,gninrom txen taht tfel yehT
.ecaf sih no elims a dah eh dna
,roolf eht no peels I fI"
etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.ahpla eht yllaicepse ,maiL ot ralimis os demees lla yehT
.t'ndid eh sgniht gniwonk fo kcank a dah eh dna
,deffocs eninac ehT
.did syawla eh ekil ,ekoj a mih gnillet saw dad siH
.llams ro gib saw eh fi rettam on ,mih evol syawla dluow dna
.esirprus htiw depmuj maiL dna "!oN .wE"
.ecnartne eht ot dehcuorc dna
.yawa og ll'yeht dna fles gniyonna ruoy eb tsuj ,uoy ot klat ot seirt enoynA
pu gnikcits elfir a fo lerrab eht htiw sseflow a
.ytic eht hguorht deunitnoc yehT ".enif eb ll'tI"
.tleb sih delkcubnu neht dna ",elas rof t'niA"
.syawyna did eh hguoht ,flesmih ffins ot deen t'ndid eH
.sdaeh rieht ni gnitteg yb slamina llams ni erul taht seinoloc redips elttil tsuj er'yeht yllausU .srevaeW"
.uoy htiw nwod og ll'I nehT
.rof gnikool saw eh tahw ees madA did
"?em htiw ynnuf gnieb uoy erA"
.swalc prahs dna sgnaf gib dah sretsnom emoS
.thgie dah emos dna sgel ruof dah sretsnom emoS
".tnemesab eht ni looc tpek dna delaes mah dekoms emos dna yrtnap eht ni sgge tog ev'I"
.meht fo tser eht morf selkcuhc tog sdrow reH "?ti rof tnaw uoy tahW
,kcapkcab sih nepo dellup eh sA
,liof munimula fo teehs a tuo dellup eH
,llits nevE .egdub t'ndid tI
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR  .ylimaf sih htiw
,dnoces doog a rof ti tuoba gnikniht retfa ,neht dna ,dias eh
tsirw sih barg mih tel yltnatculer maiL
,hgU  "?tnemelttes eht morf yawa raf os evil uoy od yhW"
.kcab sih no eno eht ekil selfir htiw pot no nem ,etag eht ta doots srewot owT
.rood eht ot gnitniop ,dias madA
,dnuora saw regnevacs lavir ro rettauqs a nehw gnillet on saw erehT
,elzzum ni sdrow erew erehT
,mih derussaer netram enip eht tub
.sregnevacs deraperp-lli ot dehcatta llits ,dnaletsaw eht derettil meht fo sdnasuohT
dekoorc daeh s'maiL
,pu tnew elzzum s'flow ehT
.siht ekil sgniht od t'ndid yehT
—tsuj I" ,denialpxe eh
.drah gnitnap llits ,hcuoc eht ot no depmulf madA
.eil s'maiL t'nsaw tI .eiL
,flesmih ekil sregnevacs ekilnU
.seye sih otni kcab llor sraet eht gnittel
.niaga ebirt sih ot mih tog eh nehw ti peek flow eht tel dluoc eh taht derugif eH
.tarb a ekil deifiralc maiL
.dnaletsaw citpylacopa-tsop siht demaor taht seno eht
.oot elpoep kcirt ot hguone gnorts er'yeht ,gib oot teg yeht nehw taht draeh ev'I
.oot flow saw tnecs sih dnA !erehwyrevE
,levarg delgrag ehs ekil
.rehtom sih dna maiL neewteb derahs egnahcxe on saw erehT
,ecnelis s'etunim a retfA
.noisnam eht ecnis emit tsrif eht rof elims-flah a gnikcarc ,deggurhs eH
.kcab gnikcilc sremmah elpuoc a fo dnuos eht raeh dluoc eh erows madA
em revo lla gnilwarc ,snoillim erew
,deunitnoc eh dna
"?enim morf ssorca thgir eno ehT
.pirt eht fo tsom teiuq
,dias eh ",sseug I .enif
.revoc fo tuo deklaw dna daeh sih deddon tub
".ot tnaw t'ndid I sgniht od em gnikam dna
.dlrow remrof eht fo sniamer eht ta gnikcip ni detseretni t'nerew sretnuH
",tif nac I kniht I"
,msaisuhtne s'yob eht nees dah madA
.flah ni sreltna eht gnippir dna ffo kcapkcab sih gnillup
.edam eh ekatsim eht erus ton ,gnicar saw dnim s'madA
.eraps ot ytnelp dah madA
.ni yaw sih ezeeuqs ot ydaer tuoba
.tsrif og ll'I .nac uoy eruS"
.pu smra sih gniworht
.ereht yaw eht detniop dna sredluohs sih deggurhs eh oS
.delknirw tuons reh fo pit eht dna stils ot deworran seye reh htoB .nworf a ni
".rettisybab a ton m'I"
"?thgir ,stah ekil uoY
.niaga reve maiL truh meht fo yna tel ot gniog t'nsaw madA  .oserom ,srehtO
.mih eciffus dluow rewsna sih gnipoh ,dias eh
.meht morf yawa puorg a sa klaw ot gnitrats dna yawa gninrut
.epan sih otni desimorp eh
.denrub mra sih ,enog enilanerda eht htiW
.seye reh ni egnellahc a
.owt no deklaw dna thgirpu doots srehtO
.dnuorg sih dloh ot thguof maiL sa drawrof spets wef a teg ot gniyrt ,dedaelp madA
.srae reh dniheb toof a
maiL "?thgir ,ssadab eb ll'taht dna dekoorc kool ll'yeht
,tmaerd madA nehw dnA
.guh a otni mih koot dna dehgual rehtaf sih
",was I tahw ees dna ereht nwod emoc ot tog yllaer uoY .madA"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,nehctik dna smoor hguorht ,esuoh eht nwod dna pu ,setunim neetfif doog a rof mih desahc eH
,daeh sih koohs dna ahpla eht ot kcab dednuor eh
,detag saw ronam ehT
,retnec eht ni thgiR
,pu dekool yob eht nehW
.delknirw elzzum ,ylmrif daeh sih koohs madA
,tpels yob eht sA
",uoy pleh t'nac I .flesruoy no smelborp tup uoy ekil sdnuos tahT"
,kcirt siht fo draeh neve I ykcul er'eW
,dehgis eh "?yllaer toN"
"?I t'nera ,gninrom eht ni em tsniaga pu delruc uoy dnif annog llits m'I
,ta er'yeht erehw em llet uoy fI"
.pu kcab stnap sih dellup eh erofeb was yeht erus gnikam ,tuo dellac eh
”thgilyaD eht fo sretsnoM“
tnemom eht litnu pu desahpnu deniamer ohw ,ognid eht ot don a evag eH
,htob rof kniht I
.saw ezag sih revo deggof woh tsuj ees won dluoc eH
,dias eh ,reh ot ti evag eh nehW
detanimon saw ”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“ ,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
,dias dna denway maiL ,gnillum llitS
,daeh sih ni wonk t'ndid eh taht eciov taht
.dinac a no nees reve d'eh naht rediw ,ediw tnew seye s'flow ehT
.mih rof ereht syawla erew yeht dootsrednu eh hguoht
,stop leets sselniats mih gnisimorp
,pots t'ndid yehT
.seye sih desolc dna
.yawa mih gnillup dna kcapkcab sih yb yob eht gnibbarg
.drawrof wap a detsurht ycuL  .kcapkcab eht
.doowylp yb rehtegot nworts skcahs tsuj erew sgnidliub eht fo tsoM
.deb eht ot evom a ekam t'ndid tub ,deddon maiL
,tuo deirc eh "!yeH"
.did ydaerla maiL naht redrah neve dekool dna ,rekciht
,mih derongi madA
",uoy rof ton si noitamrofni taht wonk uoY"
,mih naht rellamS
;elzzum reh no elims dekciw a ,deksa ehs
,klaw etunim neetfif a ylnO
,ylyhs deksa eh ,dnuorg eht ot elzzum sih htiW  "?haeY"
elzzum reh ffo deppird ti litnu deggas elims gnikcom reH .ereht t'nsaw tI
.flow eht htiw gnola yalp ot gniyrt ,dias madA
.ahpla eht ot tneulosni erew sregnarts nehw ti ekil t'ndid ebirt ehT
.sehctiwt ni kcab gnillup elzzum sih
.niap ni lwoh elttil a tuo gnittel dna
.teef sih delffuhs maiL
.reh evom t'ndid tI
.toohs eht morf tuo dekop daeh s'flow ehT
.ti od mih dah evah t'ndluow mom siH
.mih fo ffo steehs eht gnirettulf dna ekawa flesmih gnillup ,depsag eH
",eerf rof siht evah lla nac uoy tuB"
.flow elttil eht ta gnirats dekcoc sworbeye ,denrut erew secaf rieht llA  .tnur eht saw eH
.secnereffid rieht ees dluoc eh ,meht ta dekool yllaer eh nehw ylno saw tI
.sbals etercnoc yb decrofnier
,derepsihw eh "!og ,og ,oG"
,gninepo eht sdrawot mih gard yllacitcarp ot dah eH
"?edart a rof taht s'woH
.skcirb eht revo rehtona eno gnipleh hcae
,dehctiwt sreksihw s'madA  .hturT
,thgir laeh t'nod yeht fI"
,pirt rieht ot yad a dda thgim tI
demaercs dna deraor buc ehT
.tsrif tah laiceps ruoy raew ot deen uoY .rebmemeR"
mih devol ylimaf siH
.htiw deteerg saw eh elims detsiwt emas taht otni kcab elzzum reh gnillup tsuldoolb a
,meht ekil saw taht gnihtemos gniees yellav ynnacnu na gnicneirepxe saw puorg eht ekiL
",snap dna stop leets sselniats fo sderdnuh tog neve ev'yehT
,mmH"  .emoh ekat ot mih rof stop leets sselniats neve ebyam ,kceH
".ni og ot uoy llet ot tnaw t'ndid I .yrros m'I"
.maerd siht ni net ylno saw eh esuaceb driew saw hcihw
..remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
.taem fo parcs a rof htiw delbmag eh nam a saw erehT
.keep a kaens thgim eh ekil kcab teehs reh dellup neht dna ,dias ehs
.stirips rehgih hcum ni saw yob eht
.meht ot saw yob eht tahw won litnu ti ezilaer t'ndid eH
.sesnes sih demlehwrevo reh morf maiL tcetorp ot deen lautcnitsni nA
,gnola lla taht enod ev'dluoc eh
.stun deird fo sgab erom owt tuo gnillup dna dnatsthgin a ot gniklaw ,seye sih dellor madA
.ereht nwod evort erusaert s'tI"
,ytirailimaf fo esnes yna htiw
,sesruc ni kcab deraor sevlow ehT
—rorrim eht ni flesmih ta kool ot elba eb reven d'eH
".yrros saw I dias I"
"?deb ym ni uoy erew lleh eht yhW !uoy yb ylnO"
.edisni morf sdnuos eht ot yltnetni gninetsil ,detiaw madA
a tahT" ,elkcuhc a htiw deksa dna eltsihw llactac a tuo tel ahpla eht ,renroc eht nrut dluoc madA erofeb tsuJ
.drawrof gnivom deppots eH
.yltnatcepxe ti koohs ehs dna tuo tnew wap reH .dehguoc ehs
.kcab mih dellup deirt dna redluohs eht yb mih debbarg madA ,edisni kcab lwarc dluoc flow eht erofeB    .ecno toN
sreltna s'foohrednuht eht fo flah gniniamer eht ta gnieye saw rellet yreve taht ees dluoc flow eht nevE
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
.dniheb semalf ,meht fo tnorf ni sniatnuom ,ytreporp eht morf deklaw owt ehT
—daeh s'flow eht revo liof eht desiar ylluferac eh— ",yrev"
.drawrof detniop madA
.ytic eht fo trap htuos tsom eht sdrawot ,sniatnuom eht decaf seye siH
",tey ereht ni og t'nac uoY .ysae ,yeH"
.draug eht ot erutnevda elohw sih gninialpxe ,ognid eht ot txen gnidnats saw maiL
.tsehc sih ot eson sih thguorb eh dna
.madA sa ega emas eht dekool ehs hguoht
.ni peels ot deb a dna kcol ot rood a dedeen tsuj yehT
,traeh sih ni evol rieht htiW
.kcab thgir eb ll'I"
dias eh ",si ti erehT"
,ti no doolb saw erehT
.sretnilps ni trapa nrot esuoh eht fo tser eht
.buc flow eht rof taht od ot tfel eno on eb d'ereht
.enif t'nsaw tI  .eiL  ".enif s'tI"
".nwot ot teg ew nehw niaga denaelc meht teg ot deen annog m'I woN
".skaolc eulb lla ylbaborP
,flesmih fo ffo kcapkcab eht erot maiL
.gniees saw eh tahw fo erus ton
.ecno ta gninrut sdaeh
?dnuora meht nees uoY
,hturt eht saw tI
,yriah steg ti fo ro gnihtyna ees uoy fi tuB"
.epaga ylthgils elzzum
,ylimaf sih fo demaerd eH
".noitcerid thgir eht ni em tniop ot enoemos deen tsuj I"
.flesmih fo erusnu elttil a llits
.hcrot a htiw ffo thgif ot dah eh relwarcthgin a tuoba seirotS
.pu kool t'ndid eH
,detrats madA ",yllautcA"
maiL "?gniog ew era erehW"
.sgab owt gnibbarg dna nepo gnillup
,yllufreehc demialcxe madA ",tah ruoy ,hA"
.seye rieht ni yvne htiw
.tluaf sih saw ti ,truh saw yob eht fI
.enot ylohcnalem reh ni deksa ehs "?ssenisuB"
.tuoba uoy ot klat ot detnaw I tahw s'tahT"
.setag rieht edistuo evil dluow enoyna yhw dnatsrednu ylbissop t'ndluoc klof esehT
.skaolc eulb ni lla ,sevlow fo puorg a was eh ,renroc eht dednuor eh nehW
",thgirla s'tI .nom'C"
.seitreporp evitcaoidar dna sedih rieht rof stsaeb eht nwod desahc yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
",meht fo ynam os erew erehT"
.dab taht saw eh kniht t'ndid eH
.redluohs sih revo wap a gnisiar ,drawrof gnivom mih tpek eH
.tsafkaerb rof s'tahW"
,thgin tahT
".flesym kcen sti pans ll'I"
.ta tis ot retto eht rof ksed a dna yponac a tsuj yllaer saw tI
.mih htiw deb ni kcuns dah maiL taht dezilaer eh erofeb lwoh elttil gnirepmihw a dna ,sknilb lareves koot tI
.sretnuH .tnemelttes eht fo trap htuos eht ni nwod ebirt llamS .ereh er'yehT"
.ecaf reh no feiler fo kool a ees ot gnitcepxe ,ahpla eht ot kcab denrut madA
".ti fo thguoht reveN .onnud I ?yllaer ton tuB ?ebyam ,naem I"
.ydaerla naelc dekcip neeb evah stnemelttes eht dnuora ffuts eht llA
,sruof lla no tog ,deddon maiL .ti otni troffe eht tup yllaer reven tub
,buc eht dnuora delruc eH
.tluah ot nageb ylwols maiL
".esac ni tsuj kcapkcab ym ni munimula fo teehs a tpek syawlA
,daeh sih koohs flow ehT
,maiL ot kcab klaw ot tuoba saw eh erofeb tsuj dna
.spil sih fo sedis eht nwod gniretaw loord
.dnoces a ni enog saw dna
,flesmih decarb eh — "laiceps"
.ytilibisiv mumixam erusne ot ssa sih evoba hgih pu gnah liat sih gnittel
".stah ekil I ,naem I"
",niaga neppah reven ll'tI"
"?ycuL ,emit elgnis yrevE"
,tnaem sdrow eht tahw dnatsrednu ot deirt eH
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
"?dekcatta gnieb ew erA"
"—ssa taf ruoy esuaceb tsuJ"
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no
.onnud I" ,gniyas erofeb dnoces a rof ti dehctarcs eH
.thguoht madA .sretnuH
,dehtuom dna xaler sredluohs sih tel draug ehT
.kcar eht fo wolg eht htiw etaidar ot demees seye reH
,ylizal tuoba tfird ot demees daeh siH
. elggurts ot deunitnoc eh sa ria eht otni dekcik sgel siH "!ehtaerb t'nac I" ,tuo deirc eh dna mra s'netram eht fo ffo emac waj s'maiL
.gninepo na dnif ot gniyrt ylsseltiurf
,hgual a dekrab madA
.tup deyats yob ehT
,ekoj eht teg t'ndid eh nehw dna
.mih sdrawot yaw rieht gnitrats srebmem kcap evissergga erom eht fo emos raeh dluoc eH
.sbuc rieht devol srehtoM
.dnim sih no elfir eht ,kcapkcab eht fo parts eht debbarg eH
dna gnitnuoc no sucof tsuJ
.redluohs eht no mih dettap madA
.mom sih morf sessik dna sguh neve dna ,serusaert suordnow ,sgge dna mah
.toohs eht morf gniltsur a saw erehT
.ereht t'nsaw maiL ,dnuora denrut eh nehw tub ,flesmih dniheb gninoitom ,deplug eH
.stun dna stiurf deird fo tsafkaerb sih tae maiL tel dna ,feiler ni hgis a tuo tel eH
.flesmih detcerroc eh neht tuB  .hturT
.mih dednimer madA ",egaugnaL"
".emit em emos ekil I
.yrujni sih pu kcehc ot hcuoc eht ssorca gnihctoocs ,flesmih ta desruc madA
.thgir saw eh taht mih dlot daeh sih edisni eciov taht tub
",ecin yrev t'nsaw tahT"  ".yrroS"
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.yltew elzzum sih otni kcab ti depruls eh nehT
",noos os pu ew er'yhw —er'yhW"
.redluohs s'yob eht dettap dna
".gnihton esol t'ndiD"
;thgilyad eht fo sretsnom eht fo thguoht eH
,kcab tnew daeh siH
.ecnartne na rof esuoh eht delcric yeht sa mih dniheb yats maiL dah madA
.skaolc rieht ,selzzum rieht ,ruf riehT
.og mih tel reven eh ,lla ti hguorhT
.noisufnoc htiw thguorw ,meht fo lla revo dekool madA
.eno evah nac uoy
,drawrof deppets puorg eht fo ahpla ehT
sllaw llat eht yb detcetorp
.denoitnem dah ycuL
?uoy ro taht od eH ?kcar foohrednuht
,ti tuoba gniknihT  ".rood
.mih rof gnorts gnieb saw maiL tuB
.seye sih fo tuo dnas eht debbur eh sa gninaorg
.od ot tuo tes eh tahw enod dah eh taht deveiler gnileef ,dias eh
.semit elpuoc a dray eht dnuora neve dna
.dnuorg eht ot deppid llits elzzum
.seirettab eht yrrac mih pleh ot nwo sih fo kcapkcab a nevig saw maiL
,ylimaf dna sretsis dna srehtorb ym yb dednuorrus saw I ,pu gniworg
.tsehc s'madA otni knus kcab sih htiw gnirons yltfos saw maiL
.gnidnats saw maiL erehw ot kcab daeh sih degdun eh
,pu tnew worb reH
sgel sih neewteb saw liat siH
.emit hcum oot meht tsoc dah ruoted rieht ,detcepxe madA sa tsuJ
.nwod dna pu flow eht deye dna detsiwt elzzum s'netram enip ehT
.espylacopa-tsop ni erar saw taht romuh fo esnes a dah netram enip redlo ehT
.krow dluow ti fi erus t'nsaw I hguoht
,maiL fo og tel ot deirt madA
.snoitpo reh gniredisnoc ,htrof dna kcab dekool ehS
",tsafkaerb rof pu sepoh ym gnitteg tuoba ,oN"
,elbbur eht revo delwarc yehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.netram enip eht ecaf ot gninrut ,deppots navarac elohw ehT
.yb esolc stnemom tsal eseht dneps ot detnaw netram enip ehT
,yawa mih del madA  ".doG knaht"
"—ot gnilliw eb d'I
",gnihtemos tsol syug uoy kniht I !yeH"
morf emac yeht erehw ot kcab dekool eh nehT
.ereh teg ot hguorht neeb d'yeht tahw fo thguoht netram enip eht
,dnuora nups madA
",daeha syaw elttil a tsuj s'eH .yug a tog I"
,deggurhs navarac eht fo tsoM
,citehtap yletulosba dekool flow ehT
.kcapkcab sih fo parts a dnuora pirg mih gnikam raef ,deksa madA
.syawyna mih ot gnulc ti fo tsom tub
.gnidliub eht dniheb gnidih flow eht gniciton
".ti tcepsorp ot elba neeb reveN
,ruf sih otni taht desimorp
.deb eht ot gnitniop ,ecnelis eht kaerb ot tsrif saw netram enip ehT
,no eunitnoc dluoc yeht erofeB  .hturT
.esor kcen sih fo kcab eht no selkcah ehT
yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof
etoyoC triD yB
.gnidliub a dniheb renroc a nrut puorg a dehctaw sa tsuj
.niaga mraf eht fo tmaerd madA
.no denael dna ot txen kcapkcab sih deppord eh taht redluob a
,dias dna ognid eht ot maiL dellup madA
.sevaw ni pu gnilwarc sredips noillim A .meht was madA
,detaeper dna worb sih deworruf madA  .derepmihw eh
.maiL fo tmaerd eh
.seert eht hguorht noisnam a ees dluoc eh ,hguoht daetsnI
.deb evissam a no rehtegot deldnub meht fo lla
.draug eht deksa
.nwod dna pu gniddon ,dias buc eht ",rehtegot edisni og ll'ew dna tah eht no tup ll'I"
.tnemesab eht ot del taht toohs a tpec llA
,erutnevda na neeb dah syad wef tsap esehT
,mih rof dnim ni dah eh noitseuq revetahw ekil t'ndid eH
.ecnartne eht ot gnigrahc sgniht elttil ytsan fo sdnasuohT
",flesym rof kool tsuj ll'I ,wonk uoY—"
.drawrof flow eht gnihsur
.nwod dnats ot sevlow eht fo tser eht rof wap a gnivaw ,detrats ehs
",tif nac I kniht t'nod I ,maiL"
.dlog ni thgiew sti htrow saw esuoh detcepsorpnu yletelpmoc A
.noziroh eht htiw gnola ,ylsuoicipsus meht gnieye
.ti sdrawot gniklaw morf maiL pots t'ndid tahT
.sdoow eht ni eramthgin citpylacopa-tsop rehtona saw ti taht dnoces tilps a rof deirrow ,denrut madA
.sdnif rieht tcetorp ot ydaer
.hud ,ekil tub ,eiL
,dias dna flow ot denrut neht eH
:dnim sih ni srepsihw rieht draeh eh
.elzzum sih gnivruc elims llams a saw erehT
.gnisir kcen sih fo kcab eht no selkcah eht ,eloh eht ta nwod dekool madA  .eiL
mih ot detaeper madA ",egaugnaL"
,gniyas erofeb gnaf a ta kcil ot htuom reh denepo ehS
.yaw eht lla mih gnieye-edis ,drawrof deppets flow ehT  ".kcab kool t'nod
.mih derussa madA
.daeh sih no tif dluoc ti taht os pu ti gnilwob
.guh a otni buc eht dellup eh
.buc eht ta gnitniop ,kciuq saw madA
.ylhsipeehs deddon maiL
.daeh sih no riah a truh reve t'ndluow rehtom siH
”thgilyaD eht fo sretsnoM“ fo
",kool ot ton uoy dlot I" ,dessih madA
.noitatuper ym mrah yllaer nac taht ekil noitamrofni gniviG" ,dias ehs nehT
,tuo deffocs madA
".eman ym wonk uoY"
.kcapkcab sih ffo gnillup elihw wap a pu gnidloh
.tif ot madA rof llams oot tub
erehT" .gnilffins llits ,seye tohsdoolb sih gnibbur saw flow ehT
,desruc eh "!tignad hsoG"
".stah ekil t'nod I"
,gniksa ,drawrof pets a koot maiL
.dnuorg eht decaf elzzum sih dna
,eloh eht hguorht deirc madA "!maiL"
.dlrow eloc a s'tI"
—drawrof deppets madA— ",yrev A"
.desuap neht dna ,dias ehs ",tiaW"
,revo mih dekool madA
.ylimaf wen sih htiw evah dluow eh serutnevda eht fo tmaerd eH
".roolf eht ekat ll'I
,kcab gnorts eb t'ndluoc madA fi tub ,riaf t'nsaw tI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
.pu ti kcol ot yek thgir eht dnif ot reverof gnikat madA
,derettum netram enip ehT
.live erew sretsnom emoS
,yleerf tuoba gniklaw erew nemow dna neM
.rellet a ot gnitniop ,deksa eh
.rood a hguorht yaw ym xa dna kcab emoc ll'I dna em llac uoy
.ynit saw rehtaf siH
".daehbmud a er'uoY" .kcab mih devohs dna dehgual maiL
,yls eb ot gniyrT ".tuoba
.edisni kcab lwarc ot nwod gninrut ,dias flow eht
.yawa gniklaw ydaerla saw eh tub ,tsetorp ot dekool maiL ".yawa
.tnemtaert siht ot desu saw madA
.smra sih ni pmil tnew yob eht litnu mih ehtoos ot gniyrt
,palf latem eht tsniaga elttar meht draeh eH  .depacse gnihtoN
,kaeps ot ydaer saw madA  .mom sih saw ehS
.ebirt sih ot kcab mih teg ot gniyrt m'I dna pu mih dekcip I .flow tahT"
"?dnoces a mih revo hctaw uoy naC"
".moordeb rehto eht dnif t'ndluoc I"
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT    .daeha emoh
.edisni daeh sih kcuts maiL
,detuohs madA ",luferaC !yeh ,yeH"
.mih ta kool ot pu daeh sih gninrut
,oga gnol erew seybdoog riehT
.doog pu dedraob si ecalp taht ,haN"
,ffo ti gnihsurb deirt eh ,yllacitnarF
"?ylenol teg uoy t'nod tuB"  .t'ndid tI
.tuo dna ni teg t'nac I naem t'nseod ,tif t'nac ttub taf ruoy esuaceb tsuJ"
.eb dluoc srehto htiw gnieb doog woh mih dednimer dah flow eht
.kcab s'yob eht dnuora depparw madA
.yaw eritne eht mih gnithgif buc eht
,esraoh saw eciov reH
.yawa saw ylimaf sih nehw was eh sgniht eht tuoba dettahc eH
.gnilaeh saw flow eht dna yrd saw tI
.deggurhs dna seye sih dellor eH
wohs eht dnif ro
.erawrevlis dezirp neve dna ,seno gib ,sVT eb dluoc erehT
,ecneirepxe eht morf pu koohs ytterp llits saw maiL
,deksa maiL "?madA ,yeH"
,ylwols gninepo eht morf tuo delwarc eH
.ecnatsid a morf neve ,suoivbo saw tI
,dnuorg eht morf esor latem fo steehs llaT
maiL etinuer nac madA erehw
.kcab sih no sreltna foohrednuhT eht dewohs dna dnuora kcapkcab sih denrut madA ,gninaorG  .yltalf dias ehs
,kcab rieht ot tniopkcehc eht dna
.tlahpsa eht revo deparcs teef s'flow ehT
,nwod mih mlac ot deirt eH
.nwo sih no evivrus dluoc yob siht woh esnes ekam ot gninnigeb saw tI
",mih ta kooL .ebirt ruoy s'eH"
,lrans a ni kcab gnillup elzzum s'buc eht gnihton
.denepo eb ot etag eht rof dellac yeht dna ,dehcaorppa yeht sa devaw eH
.neewteb ni seil elttil emos ylnO
,hsuh a ni dias dna ,thgir dna tfel elzzum sih deppilf eH
,emoh yenruoj rieht ot yawflah er’yehT
.teehs reh ta regnif a gnitniop ,deksa eh
.eciffo ecnailpmoc tfihsekam eht rof tnorf ni doots eh sa denaorg madA
.mih ta pu delims flow ehT
tnorf rieht ot sniatnuom eht htiW
,reggib erew sevlow ehT
.dnuora nups flow eht
delddas dna detpuretni eh
.eciov sih gnirewol
.meht fo owt eht ot decar yeht sa dekcalc dna dekcilc segadneppa riehT
,gniyas erofeb nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon flow ehT
.segadnab eht gnikcehc
,levon a gnitirw si
.ot desu saw eh seno gib eht ekilnu yletelpmoc ,llams saw guh sih tuB
.htiw gnidart sih fo tsom enod dah eh tnemelttes eht saw teerts eht morf thgiartS
,mra s'netram enip eht pu dehctap yehT
.sregnif sih dessim ylerab tsuj tI
.ycnegru s'madA ot no thguac neht tub ,dias eh
.yhtrowtsurtnu dna tsenohsid saw ti tuoba gnihtemoS
.ruf sih htaenrednu toh gnileef niks ,ydob eritne sih hguorht desruoc doolB
.edis sih yb mih gnipeek
.kcen sih ot dehcatta ylluf gnikool ton
.daeha daor eht ta gnikool ,detrats eh ",madA"
.edis s'netram enip eht ot pu gnittort