,mih gnihcuot ygrene gniraes a ekil saw hcuot ehT
,meht fo riap eht
elliryC .dnabsuh driht reh no detaehc rafa morf sydalG dna
,deb eht no erehT
.revo lla mih kcil ot devol ehs dna
.rehtie gnol tsal t’ndluow taht tub
.avilas flowerew eht ot sknaht deeps kcen-kaerb ta
lrans did ehs tub
,sih ot ezag reh denrut ehS .yldas delwoy dna
.kcirp sih ot gniod saw eh tahw fo weiv lluf a
,noitanimreted s’elliryC saw
ydob tliub ylbanosaer tub ehtil sih dna
,sriaffa fo etats etanutrofnu das a saw tI
,sselerutaef dekool tI
,kcoc sih tsniaga delbmert sllaw lanigav reH
,redluohs thgir s’narF tfel reven seye sih dna
.gniteerg ni noom eht ot delwoh dna
.ti htiw od ot gnihton dah
,liat demrof ylwen sih ot
,yppah saw eh tsael tA
.seot sih no mih gnipeek dna
.mih dlot narF gnihtyreve ni gnikat
,niks eht kaerb ot erus edam ehs ,emit sihT
.tnemesab eht ot yaw sih edam dna
sregnif sih fo tuo deppils lortnoc sa
,seenk sih no pu tas elliryC
.desucofnu dna detatneirosid
daeh sih ot gnimoc sdnah sih ,bos a tsomla
.ni evag yllanif elliryC litnu
,avluv a saw daetsni tfel dna
”…yalp ot tuo gnimoc uoy fo edisni tsaeb taht ees I nehW
,saw ehs ereh …teY
elliryC ”?ekil skool flowerew ruoy tahw nees reve uoy evah ,yeh
.ylhtnom derrucco taht raw siht gnisol morf
.gniklat eht lla od noitome war tel yeht sa
evig dluow namuh lamron yna naht lworg rewol hcum a
flesreh gniraperp tuohtiw dna
…seye reh dna kcab dellup srae
J“ .yltnerappa ,taht denrae t’ndah eH
.spih sih ot thgir yletelpmoc nwod knus ehs ,)did reven ehs(
enola tfel gnieb derreferp eh
,dniheb elliryC tfel eh fi flesmih htiw evil ton dluoc narF
.resolc tog ehs sa rethgit nwod gnipmalc dna ni mih gnikcus
.ti teg ot gnihtyna yrt dluow dna
”.gnol siht dnuora kcuts ev’I“
.siht od nac uoy ,evol no emoC“
,stiw sih fo tuo deracs gnieb derebmemer narF
,noitamrofsnart siht hguorhT
.selbbird ni ylwols ydob sih nwod wolf ot der fo senil gnivael ,drah tib ehS
”…dna gnitae t’nerew uoy …nehw oS“
,mih revo delwarc elliryC sa kcoc sih fo og gnittel sdnah sih
,enod saw rac eht nehW
.dah eh tahw htiw detcilfni eb ot narF detnaw reven eH
,stsaerb gnicnuob reh fo
,did sgod ekil hcum ,dezeens ehS
.niaga emit taht tsomla saw ti wenk eh dna
.htaerb peed a koot narF
pu tas flow eht sa lufeye na tog eh ,thgiled s’narF ot hcuM
,elttil a ffo dekcab ehs ,nehT
.sgniht wef a ylno saw ereht ,ereH
.dne eht ni deen t’ndid yeht
,noitamrofsnart eht morf dezad
,nalp doog a ekil sdnuoS“
,sih tsniaga ydob reh gnibbur
.ti fo ecruos eht ylekil yrev saw gniyd ylbissop mih fo eracs eht
.edisni deniamer taht yek eht htiw ti gnikcol
.tsehc sih ta dehctarcs dna
.eralg tseb sih mih evag elliryC nehw neve ton
?esiwrehto gnol os rof edis s’elliryC yb kcits ot tnaw dluow esle ohW
,hturt eht ruofuD dlot elliryC nehw nevE
elliryC .tceffe derised sti dah ti tub
edis s’elliryC evael ot desufer eh htnom yreve
.yltnenamrep ;uoy yb dekram neeb ev’I
saw sihT      .emas eht lla
,flow eht ot desigolopa llits eH
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,no gnireffus ruoy fo emos ekat ot yppah
.esor thgilnoom eht dna deraeppasid yllanif nus eht sa
,emoh ti edam
,on yletulosba mih dlot elliryC
.noitcaer ni flow eht otni pu tsurht dna
,desserdnu ydaerla saw narF
,tsam lluf ta ydaerla saw kcoc siH
ssik gnihsurc a otni spil s’elliryC ni gnikat
.narF naht ecneitap erom htiw nam a tem reven d’eh
,tsaeb eht fo deifirret dna gnilbmert
.ekatsim elbirroh
.kcul fo tol elohw a dna narF
mih denethgirf ti dna
.rehtie ffo teg ot flow eht ksa ot egaruoc eht evah t’ndid osla narF tub ,snaem yna yb thgil t’nsaw ehS
.drah dna gnol thguoht I ,oS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil
.deb eht ot nwod mih gninnip
,latipsoh eht ot og ot deen d’eh litnu
.mih rof ydaer erew sgniht erus ekam ot reilrae emoh emac syawla eH
.eb ot gniog erew yeht woh dna
.yllufitip denaorg dna
.deyarteb neeb dah ehs fi sa
purys toh saw thguoht eh tahw leef ot gniyfirret
nwod raf spih reh gnitsurht emit siht
.rotcod a detisiv eh os
,laerrus saw tI .krow ot gnitteg
stnap otni erom denrut slworg reH
,yadot krow otni emoc ot derehtob eh yhw derednow eH
detagnole tuons sih sa avilas htiw gnippird ,suomonev dna
.no flowerew eht degge dah eh
pans ot snigeb ydob sih sa
.nrubtraeh ekil tlef ti
,timda ot dah
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.deunitnoc eh sa eenk sih dnuora dehcnub steehs tevud eht ta nwod dekool dna deddon narF
.gnihgual eno eht saw elliryC tub
ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ecaf sih no elims a dna pu gniraet seye sih ,pu dekool narF
,taorht sih tsniaga dnah reh gnihsup reh ni detluser semit ynam oot taht gnioD
mih ta deffins ylno ,dne eht ni ohw
,seiceps sih naht erom degnahc
.sgnaf reh htaeneb loord ot nageb doolb
.emit gnol a rof siht tuoba thguoht ev’I tub
.won htaed ot decnetnes saw eh ,tuB
,acitore yrruf setirw ohw
.recnac hcamots lanimreT
,edisa ti dellup dna daeh sih fo kcab eht depsarg
deraeppasid nus eht erofeb emoh teg ot dedeen eH
,nwo sih no eporhtnacyl sih htiw reffus ot enola elliryC evael ot
.wohs lluf no saw
,rednerrus ni pu smra sih dleh eH
erusaelp gnikatrevo niap
tsehc sih fo tnorf eht ssorca nwod
elliryC evag taht tub
,drawrof denael ehS
.daeh reh no ruf eht hguorht dnah a nar dna drawrof dehcaer eH ”.lrig ereht yeH“
now tsaeb eht sthgin eht derebmemer reven eH
,emit taht saw ti sselnu
,esirprus ni detuohs narF
.lacol a sa ni democlew gnieb fo reirrab elbisivni emos dessap yeht litnu
.emit gnol yrev a saw taht dnA
.ffins a koot dna
,reh denraw tsael ta eH ”!…esolc m’I-I“
,detsuahxe saw eh nehw dnA
.ylevissam desaerced dah sgnirethguals dna secnaraeppasid peehs
,rehtona eno tsol ylraen dah yeht taht gnisilaer
gniyfirtcele bats llams eht
esrow teg dluow eh ,ylwolS
,rac eht gnixif saw eh tslihw evael ot desufer eH
ehcadaeh gnignab a htiw pu ekow eH
.erom mih derehtob nagro tew dna dloc eht sa narF gnivael naorg rehtona ,ereht kcab eson reh gnittup ,deffuh flow ehT
,trapa meht dellup dna mih sdrawot pu gel eht dellup daetsni tub
.revo ekat dluow edisni tsaeb eht sa
lavorppa fo lworg a htiw dnah sih otni daeh reh desserp ehS
”elliryC ,pU eM nooM“   :yojne esaelP
elliryC .enif eb dluow eh neht
daeh sih ta denetsilg erp fo sdaeB
.noitanicsaf fo tros das a htiw tiebla
,drawrof devom eH
.sriats eht nwod emac elliryC sa kniw a htiw denaorg eh dna
.evil ot shtnom dah ev’dluow I
,yenom fo tol a tsoc gnivil tub
,sdrow ynam fo nam a reven saw
.ylirgna delrans dna
,erofeb naht erom gnidneb dna
ro riaper t’ndluoc eh gnihton
.delims narF dna deggaw liat reH
,esirprus sih ot hcuM
,sih ot ezag reh denrut ehS
.hcti dna truh dluow mih fo trap yreve
”?em fo erit t’ndluow uoy yas ot s’ohW
.neppah dluow tsrow eht esac ni
,reh revo llor noitelpmoc fo sevaw nwo reh tlef ,deifsitas ,flow ehT
.namuh naht lamina erom dna rellams llits tub stsaerb
mih gninodnaba noos sdnuos namuh
,erac fles dna retfa rof yllausu
remrahc eniuqe eht ,foohnorI moK’aT yb uoy rof daer
monev eht tlef noos narF sa elbissop sa llits sa gniniamer ,evom t’ndid ehS
”?!od em tel uoy did kcuf eht tahW“
,foohnorI moK’aT yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.redluohs sih ni noitasnes gnibmun
,efil teiuq eht devil syawla dah
rehtona eno htiw kcuts erew yeht won tub
,ylkciuq tew gnitteg saw ehS
,ehca ot gninnigeb saw sivlep sih
.eson deppit kcalb a deniag dna
.tsal dluow taht gnol woh fo erusnu neeb syawla dah elliryC tub
,deredduhs eh dna kcab tsurht daeh siH
.sesiarp dna stnemmoc gniraedne sa llew sa
.emit fo tuo tsomla saw eh leef ydaerla dluoc elliryC tub
,elliryC llet ot egaruoc eht pu dekrow t’ndah eH
yb uoy rof daer ,drofwalC ecilA yb ”elliryC ,pU eM nooM“
”.taht ekil tuo dnif ot dah uoy yrros m’I“
.redluohs sih otni tib dna lrans a htiw
?emit tsrif eht tnereffid gnihtemos gnillems
.nemodba sih tsniaga thgir eson reh desserp dna ,yltnetsisni
esle enoyna morf raf devil yeht taht lufetarg ylgnisaercni tlef narF
,tuc yleritne neeb dah sdroc lacov reH
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb oirotagrruP
.mih fo pot no yal dna
ssorca skram der gnikool yrgna gnivaeL .yltneG
,srood eht kcol dna
.ruofuD narF sa gnihtyreve fo gnitpecca erom nam a tem eh dah rehtieN
detnurg narF dna
.ssenisub nwo sih dednim eh dna ti degaruocne
.wenk elliryC nihtiw flow eht
,eid ot tnaw t’ndid eH
,flowerew eht edisni niaga sevlesmeht deitpme sllab sih
regnol gnimoceb ,swalc ot egnahc dluow sregnif siH
.elliryC morf lworg a tuo gniward dna ylenecsbo spil sih gnikcil ,detnap eH
.tihs ekil tlef ,lla dna lla dna
,rehtona eno ot ’suoy evol‘ repsihw dluow riap eht ,netfo os yrevE
,lla meht derethguals t’ndah ti nosaer ylno eht dna
elliryC .em rof seod eh sgniht eht ,suseJ
,netaeb eb syawla dluow eh yllautneve tub
.suoiruf saw elliryC ”!toidi uoY“
moor eht tuoba nwerts sehtolc sih
.yldaed dna suortsnom gnimoceb
sevlesmeht gnidliuber no krow ot tog sllec dna sevren esoht sa hteet sih gnittirg
,eciv a ekil mih no nwod depmalc sllaw reH
ffo flesreh dils flowerew eht sa nialpmoc t’ndid eH
elliryC .lla t’nsaw taht tuB
,skeew rof derongi dah eh smotpmyS
gnignits dna gninrub
,erehwyreve tnecs reh gnivael
.laicurc saw ti erehw saw sihT
”.dniheb uoy evael t’ndluoc I dediced I nehw ,keew doog A
.egrahc ni saw dna
.taht ta reh fo edisni degniwt kcoc sih kcuf dna noitanimod a
.yawa dekcol dna detsuahxe
.tniop siht ta niap dna erusaelp htob neeb ev’dluoc ti hguoht
.kcab dna ecaf ,hctorc ,smra ,sgel sih
.erofeb rehto hcae dlot reve ev’yeht gnihtyna naht repeed noissimda nA
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
,sehtolc sih ffo ekat ot kciuq saw
.sesaesid ekiL
.emit ’nikcuf ruoy koot …haH“
,tey dna desylarap mra sih
.gniod saw ehs tahw ot sa erusnu saw eh dna
.eltsacsfloW otni devom eh ecnis renol a fo tib a neeb syawla
,revo dna revo kcab narF thguorb sriaper llams dna diputs rehto fo dairym A
.won yb emoh eb dluow narF gniwonk
.remrahc eniuqe eht
.ekops narF ,esuap a retfA
gninetsilg dna der erew seye siH
,htaerb a tuo tel
,nwot eht ni enoyreve morf gnipeek neeb dah elliryC terces gib eht saw sihT .flow a ot
,sdnuom dednuor won erew
,semit fo elpuoc A
,egairram rof eno t’nera ew wonk I
.gnipsag mih gnivael dna
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,yawllah eht ni sgniht sih deppord eH .t’ndluoc eh tuB
gnirekcib dna gninihw tnatsnoc s’narF litnu
nam eht tfel lrans gnilbmur dna duol a dna
.emit eritne eht mih htiw detrilf dna
,tros eht fo kcap xis a trops t’ndid eH
,uoy htiw reffus ot yppah m’I“
,gnorw saw tahw esilaer ot tnemom a reh koot ti ebyaM
,nam morf degnahc eh sa spley dna
,regnol emaceb smra sih sa dehcnurc senob siH
,narF ot sknaht ,woN
,drah desserp eh nehw ssam a ro pmul a tlef eh thguoht dna semitemos kcis gnileef
.esirprus ni ylkciuq pu tas eh dna ssentrela ot mih gnikraps
,niaga deffins ehS .deppots ehS
,riah trohs sih hguorht dnah a nar nerraW
srepmihw dna slrans otni denrut
deb eht no kcab tog eh ,bos a htiW
,kcen sih fo kcab eht dna
,lanoitome teg ot eno t’nsaw elliryC ”.yC ,uoy evol I
!evitisnes ylenasni saw tI
.yhw ot sa esucxe doog on htiw sisab raluger imes a no krow gnissim peek ot mih no doog kool t’ndluow ti dnA
.niaga derebmemer eh ,yenom ,haey hO
,degnahc seye siH
,denepo seye sih sa daeh s’elliryC gnitfil ,dednamed narF
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,niks yerg dna ruf kcalb gnol ni derevoc gnieb sediseb emas eht hcum deniamer tsehc siH
,niaga revo dna revo
.erofeb reve naht erom pu gninepo yllanif saw nam eht retfa toN .niaga ton
.desuac flesmih nam eht wenk elliryC melborp A
?!flah ni tuc teg epip tsuahxe sih did woH
,niaga daeh sih hctarcs eH ”.yrros ,haey
,yletaidemmi esol d’eh wenk eh elttab a ni ti htiw gniltserw
gnipom llits erew sregalliv eht tihs hguoT
.dluoc eh erehw pleh ot detnaw dna
!gniticxe saw ti ,sulP
,meht rof retteb saw tI
.emas eht did sgel sih dna renael
.llits nemodba sih ot yltnegru eson reh desserp neht
flow dliw tsal eht gniredrum rof eman sti tog taht nwot A
elliryC drofwalC ecilA yb
.redluohs sih gnikahs sdnah fo tes namuh a tlef eh sa denihw dna
,hguone ylkciuq niaga xif
”!?elzzum gnikcuf eht teg uoy did yhW“
,ylhguor otni nettib gnieb spil sih tlef eh sa
,mih gnidnif dna ereh gnimoc narF taht wonk yeht did elttiL
,yzarc saw eh ebyaM
.t’ndluoc srehto tsom sgniht llems dluoc yeht
,mih tuoba gnihtyreve wonk ot gnitnaw
retfa em fo kcis teg uoy fi tahw tuB“
,wolley ot neerg morf
,gnikrow saw eh nehw raeh ot niap a saw tI .cte
,ereht gnieb narF htiW
,seirots trohs rorroh sa llew sa
.gniyd saw I …yC“
,tnereffid on saw emit sihT
hguone nwod nam eht dnuorg gninialpmoc dna
,drofwalC ecilA yb
,esnopser ni gninaorg
.flesmih detsuahxe dna nohtaram a nur d’eh fi sa
.sdrow ecnim ot eno t’nsaw ssob sih yas reveN
.esuoh eht fo tser eht naht redloc tlef ti dna sllaw enots htiw
,daeh eht tsniaga spil reh debbur d’ehS
.no gniog saw tahw erusnu
,sekatsim elttil ynam os edam eH
?gninetsilg yeht erew
.ti tuoba rotcod a ees ot tnew I“
.sruof lla no drawrof denael ehs dna
,noisausrep fo slliks gnizama sih htiw oreh repus eht
.eromyna enola tfel eb t’ndluow uoy taht os
,daeh reh koohs flow eht sa ,won dewohs tahT
.deb eht tsniaga nwod sdnah sih dehsup dna delrans ehs
,elbirret a edam d’eh fi derednow eh dna
.oot did nam eht sa hcum sa narF rof derac
,raef on dleh dna suoiruc saw ehS
.enoyreve rof retteb saw tI
sa hcus seigolohtna ni dehsilbup si dna
,gnihtyna ro emufrep gnorts yna gniraew ton m’I ?ti si tahW“
,ot pu saw ehs tahw ksa dluoc eh erofeB
”.em no sucof ,erofeb semit dnasuoht a siht enod ev’uoY
tevud eht ni pu gnilruc
,ni eugnot s’elliryC wolla ot htuom sih denepo eH .yldab reven tub
”?enod I ev’tahW“ ?kcuf eht tahW
dna tniop siht ta gniredduhs erew sdnah s’nerraW
elliryC .kcab detuohs narF
,netfo os neppah ti gniees yb desitisnesed os nettog dah eh spahrep ro
dna evissessop ylemertxe tub
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.truh tlef ev’tsum ehs gniwonk
deb eht ot mih gninnip
,ylhsifles dna gniyd saw eh taht wonk tsaeb eht gnittel
.taorht sih tfel lrans eht sa esuap neve t’ndid eh
.egnahc sih hguorht mih htiw kcuts dna
,htuom sih gnivael nageb slrans dna slworg sa ecaf sih gnirevoc dna
.secived nwo sih ot dna
gniraeh wen reh htiw sdnuos eht lla ni koot ehs sa gnitlit srae reh
,ekatsim on ekam tub
lausunu dna egnarts deredisnoc erew ni gnivom sredistuo os
.peels ot ylwols mih gnillul gnimmuh emas eht
,dessih narF dna gnuts tI
nepo ti dehsup elliryC sa emit siht nepo saw tI
,egalliv eht fo mron eht ot mrofnoc t’ndid
)now syawla tsaeb eht dna(
emit eritne taht gnikahs neeb dah sdnah sih
.ti gnolorp tub mih rof rehtie od dluoc yeht hcum saw ereht taht ton
.lla ta ffo reh tup t’ndah
.rentrap sih yb ylhguor deldnah gnieb derreferp eh nehw neve
sniev sih otni nwod decreip
,esle enoyna ot kcit suovren a ekil dekool ev’thgim ti
.niap ni gninaom ,narF fo pot no despalloc dna
aibal eht dnuora dna yerg
eno siht piks nac uoy
.esruoc fo ,tuoba derac flow eht taht enoN
,tuoba emoc tsrif dah siht rof snalp nehW
,moor eht fo elddim eht ni thgir ,deb A
.llew sa xes sih tub
.reh ekil yleritne tlems eh litnu deifsitas reven saw ehS .erehwyrevE
,kcab ylper labrev yna narF gnivig fo daetsnI
,ffo flesmih teg ot stroffe sih ni llats ton did nam ehT
.tey dehsinif etiuq t’nsaw narF ,on ho tub
.redluohs dab siH
.spiuq dah llits eh
,delrans daetsni nam eht
.serusaem ytefas emertxe koot yeht sa gnol os
,demaercs nam ehT
,mih rof enif dekrow tahT
segadnab ,tik dia tsrif a
.llits neve gniworg tnemeticxe
noitasnes eht ot dedda ylno taht skcirp nip llams
,reh fo edisni dehcaerb llits daeh sih
xif ot elliryC rof rac nekorb sih htiw revo deretnuas dah nam ehT
dnah sih yb dekorts gnieb
elliryC fo edisni flow eht taht ykcul yrev deedni erew yehT
,skramer tib dna denihw ,deppiuq narF
dekcol tpek yllamron yeht rood A
,flow ladepib a rof dluoc ehs tseb sa pu lruc dluow ehs
.epahs egnahc dluow eh dna
,mih rof lufniap elttil a
.deirt t’ndah eh nehw thgiew gnisol dna etiteppa fo ssol sih
,redluohs sih hguorht gninnur
,esion eht morf yawa denrut eH
,ydaerla elbareponi saw tI
,niaga drawrof denael ehs dna
?repmub kcab rieht stned dna nib nwo rieht otni pu skcab ohw esuaceB
detnaw ehs tahw yltcaxe wenk ehS .tliops tub
,edisni taht aedi on dah
.fo kniht nac I sa esolc sa semoc siht tub
.esac ni tsuj ,elzzum a dna
.ytiniffaruF no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
dneirfyob sih evol dluow eh tub
.serutaef reh revo koot noitanimreted fo kool a dna
htiw pu emoc dah yeht tnerreted tseb eht saw tI
.moor eht fo elddim eht ni gnignah gnittif gniliec elgnis a htiw ylno til
.nettogrof d’eH
.melborp rehtona htiw retal syad kcab emac dnA
,neppah ti dehctaw narF dnA
.doom eht denepmad ev’dluow taht gnihton tub
,yllabrev ylper t’ndluoc ehS
,sseltneler saw ehS
oot gnitaews saw eH
.gniyd saw eh taht wenk ehS
,dengier llits flow eht
.em no hguor teg uoy nehw ti evol I ,kcuF“
deppots elliryC sa
drawrof denael ehs dna
,drah mih gnikcuf saw flow eht nehw neve ,esruoc fO
,deneppah siht emit tsrif ehT
.reh otni muc detrups dna deredduhs eh sa tuohs a dna msagro s’nam eht tuo gniward
.rof lufknaht saw elliryC ,hcihw fO
…ekil kool I dluow tahW
.etib flowerew eht fo kram nworb dnuor a detrops won dna
detsuahxe ylrettu saw
.eson reh htiw ecaf sih degdun dna
,tsehc sih ot thgit dneirfyob sih degguh dna
,mih revo lla eb dluow tI
.sevlesmeht egalliv eht dna
,kcoc sih tsniaga niap fo egnit eht tlef narF hguone drah dezeeuqs ehs
?eb d’I flowerew yxes fo dnik tahw rednow I“
,mih gnihcuot devol ehS
,krad saw moor ehT
,truh ot nageb tsehc siH
deffuh flow eht tub
,yhs etiuq yllautca saw ehS
,ruoloc egnahc dluow ydob s’elliryC ,ylwolS
.deyalp htob yeht emag a saw sihT
elliryC ,ruoloc eht fo skool eht yb dna
.mih no hguot eb ot gniog saw ti gniwonk
.sroirepus sih yb decitonnu yletelpmoc enog t’ndah
snaorg dna seirc s’elliryC
,mih tuoba gnihtyreve detpecca ohw evol sih dnuof d’eh
,yrt a ti evig ot gnilliw saw eh
.krad eht ni ees retteb ot did eh sa stils gniniag
.kcen sih nwod gnihtaerb reh fo ria dloc eht tlef narF litnu
,tekcop sih ni yek eht tup eH
,sredluohs sih otni gud ylneddus swalc reH
elliryC ”.esrow rof ro retteb rof
,enif ehtaerb dluoc eH
,erehwyreve niks sih fo tuo worg dluow ruf dna tuorps dluow liat a ,mih dniheB
.ruofuD narF tem eh nehT
.tluaf s’elliryC t’nsaw ti ,llitS
.redluohs sih otno dehctal dna delrans flowerew eht sa
,rehtegot devil yeht ,woN
deracs erew uoy wonk I
,trap sih rof ,narF
og tel flowerew ehT
,delrans dna delworg elliryC erehW
.emas eht tlef yltnerappa flow eht sa thgir
,taerht a ylerem saw erusserp eht
,reh hcuot ot deirt eh revenehW
knirb eht ot flesmih desaet dah dneirfyob sih sseug ot dah
.avluv reh fo sserp eht tlef ylneddus kcid gninetfos eh
nettib neeb dah taht eno eht
tirips s’elliryC peek t’ndluoc dneirfyob sih neve ,yletamitlu tub
,lortnoc fles rof regnol elttil a thgif dluoc eh ,mih gnidnuorg
.siht detnaw syawla ev’I“
,knurhs sllab dna kcoc siH
.erised lauxes yb no derul saw eh sa
?sraey derdnuh A ?sraey net
.efil sih htiw dedraug narF taht eno
meht fo htob eht rof yhtlaeh saw hcihw
esle erehwemos ti debrosba dna werg ydob sih sa gniraeppasid
,ti htiw gniltserw ,dne rettib eht litnu thgif dna thgif d’eH
,kcen sih tsniaga pu thgiR
,yad lla krow ta drah neeb d’eH
,saw emufrep tahw aedi yna dah flow eht erus saw eh taht toN
.gnihtyreve fo esnes ekam ot deirt eh sa
,dekcohs demees
.ecno naht erom kcab flesmih dleh dna
,hcamots sih ni loop ot nageb stergeR
taht detpecca syawla d’eH
,ti wenk eh erofeb dna
,dellik neeb reve dah ydoboN
,llird eht wenk narF
,evitaitini eht ekat ot dah eh semitemos dna
,dexaler fi sa dehcterts rehto eht tslihw pu saw eenk enO
.mih fo tuo erised fo naom rehtona gniward dna kcoc sih otno nwod kcab gniknis
dellihc a htiw tfel saw narF dna
ehca ot nageb ydob sih
erew sgniht woh tsuj saw ti ,saw reven tI
krims tub pleh t’ndluoc narF
,tseretni esol dluow elliryC ,semit netfO
,yllamron meht fo htob eht rof gniklat eht lla did narF
tub egalliv eht ni devil ohw skaerf owt
,dekrow ti woh erus t’nsaw eH
elliryC ,htuom sih ot ssik a desserp eH
.niaga efas eb dluow peehs rieht erew secnahc
,hcamots siht ni niap modnar gnitteg neeb dah narF ,syad roF .recnac ekiL
”.uoy htiw etad ydoolb a no og ll’I
.gnihtyreve tegrof dna thgin dna yad elohw eht
,ylper ot elbanu
,neppah ot siht gniwolla rof
hguone drah nwod gnitib
selcihev nwo ruoy gnisuba pots uoy sekam ti fI !eniF“
,edis sih yb deniamer llits nam eht
mih gniltrats eson dloc reh ,dehcnilf eH
,eunitnoc t’ndid eH
,ecaf sih dnuora strap emos did sa sselruf deniamer
.flowerew eht ot tuo taorht sih gniraeb
pu taoc sih gnignah
”!yC ,siht detnaw I esuaceB“
.kaew snaem on yb saw eh tub
.meht raeh t’ndluow yeht os
,reh fo tuo dellup htgnel sih fo trap dna gnihcterts
,doolb gniward semitemos
.yllaicepse seye sih raen
,emoh teg tsuj tub
.wodahs a gnimoceb ro enots ot gninrut erew eh fi sa
daeh sih gnidloh sdnah sih
denihw ehs dna kcab dellup srae reh ,nehT
,eno tink gnorts a saw ytinummoc ehT
.tsul ni revo dezalg seye sih dna dehsulf erom werg ecaf sih ,gnihtyna fI
.evil dluow htob yeht sa gnol sa rof
,llems fo esnes etuca na dah sgoD
,mih revo pu delruc dna hcleuqs a htiw
.hsilgnE fo scisab erab eht dootsrednu yllausu flow eht tub
,egnahc reven dluow sgniht emoS
ruonaemed elbatirri dna smlap gnikahs sih tub
,htiw revo ti teg dna deb otni espalloc ot detnaw eH
.efil xes rieht fo dias eb dluoc emas eht dna
.ffo evord eh dna no eman dna rebmun sih htiw eton a dna hsac sih deppils narF
.ti htiw laed dluoc eh erus saw eh taht
rehtegot pu delruc gniniamer riap eht
,tuo snrut ti ,serusaeM
.reh otni htgnel eritne sih gnikat dna
,shtaerb peed koot
ylthgils yawa dellup ehs
evlossid dluow ytilanosrep sih dna
”?thgi’a ,worromot retteb eb dna dneirfyob ruoy kcuf
…flow s’elliryC tub ,hA
.mih otni derocs eb dluow sgnaf reh fo gnir a
,reffus ot em tnaw t’ndid uoy dna
,rehtegot enola syawla erew yeht woh
stohs eht lla dellac ehs
,”ellivstihs gnirob siht ni od ot retteb gnihton“ dah eh gniyas
.siht rof mih llik dluow yletulosba
.edabrof flow eht tub
.seye sih dellor
rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop
,skcab rieht dniheb meht tuoba ekops syawla yehT
,dehtolc ylluf llits saw nam ehT
elliryC .dluoc ,revewoh ,ehs
.ho …nwod dekool eH
.serusaem emertxe eseht ni ylno desu
.flow eht fo slwoh dna slrans eht htaeneb elbidua ylerab saw rehtona eno tsniaga gnivom seidob rieht fo dnuos eht
gnihtyna no sucof ylerab dluoc dnim siH
.noom lluf siht retfa siht od ot dednetni ylno eh tub
.narF sdrawot gniklats dna gnilwarc
skcep llams dah ecno eh erehw tub
mih fo ffo meht gnippir tsomla
.seye s’narF erofeb thgir mrofsnart ot nageb ylwols eh sa
,reh gnitartenep eno eht neeb ev’thgim eH
,mih ot dekool ehs ,woN
.retlem ytnap dna
.noziroh eht no raeppasid ot nageb nus eht sa ti gnihctarcs
.egairram ni dnah sih deksa evah llew sa thgim eH
,mih dniheb ti desolc neht dna
,ylkciuq rood eht gnikcol dna gnisolc
elliryC .dab eht dna doog eht
swalc reh sa naorg a tuo tel neht
”.ni tog uoy erofeb flesym welb …tsomlA
,rae ot redluohs morf dekcil ehS
smeti htiw dellif draobpuc a saw kcab eht ta thgiR .eceip ertnec eht
.evah ot dekil narF tnemeticxe artxe taht dellifluf dna
”elliryC ,pU eM nooM“
,erom no mih denrut ylno ti tub
”?-eht tahW !aohW“
”,elliryC ,emoh no teG“
elliryC ”.recnac hcamots lanimreT
.rehtegot egarag eht dekcol yeht sa mih dlot ssob siH
”.yadot hguor -fgggn er’uoy-y …suseJ-
htaed noos ylemitnu sih ,wohemoS
,sekalfnroc ruoy ni dessip ohw wonk t’noD“
prahs worg dluow hteet siH
”.uoy gnitcepxe m’I nehw od reven
.won kcab dloh ot deirt eh fi denmad eb dluow eh tub
!thguoht eht dnats t’ndluoc I
.rulb noisiv sih tlef dna
.etib eht tsniaga eugnot gnol a nar dna
.pu flesti esolc dnuow eht dehctaw ehs sa rrup a ekil tsomla ,demmuh flow ehT
.sriats eht nwod emac neht
.emit siht ton ,esol ot droffa yllaer t’ndluoc eh emos
deb eht otno nwod dennip
.yhcuot yrev saw
dneirfyob sih htiw semit hguone siht hguorht neeb d’eh dna
depahser senob sa ekahs yltneloiv dna
desaec gninrub eht ,taht ekil tsuJ
,sruof lla no deb eht otno tog dna
,laocrahc ot etihw morf
.dnatsrednu llits dluoc ehs tub
,hcuot dluoc eh dehsiw eh seno
,won reverof uoy htiw eb nac I
.gniod eb ot tnaem saw eh tahw derebmemer eh sa no mih gnirrups