.eman yb meht fo lla tsomla wenk ehs taht hguone gnol ereht neeb dah ffats ehT
.retsis ym gnitaertsim enoyna etarelot t’now I ,ti naem I tuB“  .dias eh ”,fo
,retiusruf ,retirw yrruf
.epip gnorw eht otni yaw sti ekam ot deirt diuqil eht sa dehguoc dna eeffoc sih otni detrons sivaD
.dias eh ”,etal m’I
hU“	     ”.ti otni ragus emos tup uoy nehw dab os ton s’tI“
sklof dednim redlo eht fo emos yb nopu denworf yllareneg saw ti wenk ycuL
,tsirw tfel reh no telecarb elgnis a erow ehS
sivaD“	     .eman yb htob meht wenk ffats eht sraluger tneuqerf hcus erew meht fo owt ehT  .deksa ehs
”?yltcaxe ,I ma yug fo dnik tahw oS  .ton esoppus I“
.emit no tnemtnioppa tsafkaerb rieht ot ti edam eh syad tsom
.thgir er’uoy sseug
.dias ycuL ”,wonk
,ohW“	     .deksa eh ”?sruoy fo dneirfyob taht dna uoy era woh ,nem fo
,deksa ehs ”?uoy dnA“
.em ot ’sivaD reciffO‘ er’uoy ereh ni no mrofinu taht tog ev’uoy nehw tub ,os
,em ton ,nemow rehto taht ytirohtua doog ylriaf no ti evah I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.desuap neht dna nwod redro sih etorw ehS  ”.pu thgir
.tsafkaerb ym dah ev’I retfa litnu ton tub ,syawlA“
”?gge eht ekil uoy dluow woH  .esruoc
decalP	     .esnopser reh rof detiaw eh htuom sih otni taem fo etib txen eht gnippoP
.serauqs elttil taen otni ekacnap eht ecils ot nageb dna
.kaets fo etib rehtona gnitae erofeb desuap eH	     .dias ycuL
.mrofinu ecilop sih gniraew
yakO“	     .deggurhs ehS  ”.emèrc hsirI fo lluf osserpse elpurdauq a htiw pu dne thgim uoy tub ,ekil uoy fi sseug dluoc I  .wen
.kcab eht no taws lufyalp a sivaD evag ehs sselehtreveN
troS“	     ”.gniddik er’uoy epoh od I“
ycuL	     .kaets fo sebuc erom wef a eta eH
,lleW“	      ”.em fo dir teg ot gniog ylbaborp er’yeht elttil a pu gnipahs trats t’nod I fi dna taerg taht lla neeb t’nevah wef tsal ehT
.deksa ycuL ”?sreciffo wollef ruoy fo eno tuoba tahw
.detsat reve I eeffoc tseb eht si siht esac taht ni
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
A	     .taes a rof dehcraes dna seye reh denepo niaga ecno ehs erofeb neZ
sihT	     .riaf t’nsaw tI
.etuc er’uoy skniht ohw uoy llet ot deriuqer m’I eveileb t’nod I ,sediseB“
tsuJ“	     ”.sivaD reciffO ,uoy ot gninrom doog dna ,ycuL ssiM ,niaga gninrom dooG“
oS“	     .daeh reh detlit ycuL  ”?yhw
“  .puc reh htiw tsaot a rehtorb reh gnireffo ,dias ycuL
.reh fo tnorf ni ti dleh dna tibah fo tuo unem eht pu dekcip ehs
tsuJ“	      .reh ta delims flow redlo ehT
”,thgiR“	      ”.og ot deen eW  ?ereht ni uoY“
ycuL	     .noitcerid reh ni krof sih detniop eH
’noh‘ uoy llac ot deriuqer erew sessertiaw renid fi erus t’nsaw ycuL	     dias ehs
.evol lanoitidnocnu fo sraey sseltnuoc reh rof rehtom reh knaht ot rethguad doog a eb syawla ot tseb reh did ohw
diuqil fo puc nworb thgil a htiw retal stnemom wef a denruter tac eht
.llew sdne reven tI
,etisoppo eht yllausu saw ti enif erew yeht dias enoyna emityna taht wenk ehS
.deggurhs sivaD  ”?I
.taht tuoba kniht ot dah ev’I ecnis elihw a neeb s’ti ,won ,lleW“
.tnemtsujda dedeen ylerar slaem eht ecalp siht ni sgniht eht fo tsom ekil
.reniD s’ykcuL dellac ecalp elttil llams a ot yenruoj eht ekam dluow ehs yad yreve
A	      .unem eht gnidaer tpek dna nwod enohp eht tes daetsni ehs
.riah krad gnol dna taoc depirts a htiw tac ybbat yarg a saw ehS
.oga raey a tuoba detrats ylno gnivah ,seno rewen eht fo eno saw ehS
.deggurhs sivaD	     .denraw ycuL
.egareveb nwo reh otni delkcuhc
.tsafkaerb reh morf rovalf fo tib yreve tcartxe ot gniyrt elzzum reh ni dnuora doof eht dellor ehS
.rac eht otni tog ehs
gnitsugsiD“	      .puc eht otni kcab ylkciuq niard diuqil eht tel eh yawa deklaw ehs ecno dna
I“	      .seiceps a sa stiart renif rieht fo eno saw ti ycuL oT
ebyaM“	     ”.’reciffo‘ em llac ot evah t’nod uoy erofeb uoy dlot ev’I“  .dias eh
.etelpmoc eb ot nam a sdeen namow yreve toN“  .deggurhs ycuL
m’I“	      ”.eb ot tnaw uoy nehw yracs yrev eb nac uoY
”.gnol gnitiaw neeb t’nevah uoy epoh I
.pihsnoitaler s’esle enoemos ni devlovni teg reven ot si denrael ev’I gniht eno tub ,llew naem uoy wonk I
hO“	      ”.sebiv erew erehT“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.uoy yb detadimitni ylbaborp si dna poc a er’uoy swonk eH
retsaf hcum ydaer teg dluoc nem yaw eht fo suolaej gnieb yllanoisacco yned ton dluoc ehs
.sredro suoirav eht no desu gnieb sgninosaes dna secips suoirav eht lla
gnikaepS“	     ”.emit eht lla ton ,tsael tA
fO“	     ”?thgir ,uoy ot doog gnieb t’nsaw eh fi em llet d’uoy woN
htoob eht ni htob erew yeht taht
no evom ot gniog t’nsaw eh raelc saw tI
,namow a gnieb derreferp ehs hguohT
”,od I esruoc fO“	     ”?taht naem uoY“
.ria eht otni sekacnap fo lufkrof rehtona detfil ycuL
ecaf eritne reh ssorca hcterts ot hguone ediw selims esoht fo eno delims terref ehT
.tsafkaerb reh tae ot gniunitnoc erofeb
.erofeb nees reve d’ehs kniht t’ndid ehs elpoep wef a ylno erew erehT
”?yletal mom ot deklat uoy evaH“  .elims flah kaew
detsixe yllautca nosrep a hcus rehtehw ro saw ykcuL ohw wenk eno oN
.thgil eht ni denihs egdab sih dna desserp yltcefrep syawla saw mrofinu siH
yltneitapmI	      .elbmur ot trats hcamots reh edam laem derised reh fo thgis ehT
.won thgir ti ebircsed ot esle woh wonk t’nod I“
gnikooc nocab dna gniyrf sgge fo sdnuos
syad rieht trats ot yawa dellup yeht sa gnilims
.deggurhs dna deddon terref
.tsafkaerb sih tae ot gniunitnoc ylpmis ,gnihtyna yas ot ton esohc eh tub
.retsis ym gnitaertsim s’enoemos sselnU“
.lla s’taht ,won thgir era ew erehw yltcaxe wonk t’nod tsuj eW
ro erehwemos pots ot dah ylbaborp eH
,samora eht
mrof ot sah tI  .cinagro si evoL
,haeY“	     .deggurhs ycuL  ”.gib gnihton ,eludehcs eht no sgniteem wef a
ylleK	      .dettimda ehs ”,elttil A“	     .deksa eh
,t’nod I“	     .deksa eh
ehT	     .yenom eht reh gnidnah ,deksa eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
?sebiV“	     .deksa ehs ”?sebiv eht no pu kcip t’ndid
.feihcsim fo tnih a htiw delkraps dna eulb erew seye reH
rood eht ni dellorts sivaD nehw niaga enohp reh kcehc ot tuoba saw
tnuoC“	     ”?worromot emit emas owt uoy ees ,yakO“
.daeh reh koohs
wap ni krof dna efink reh koot ycuL
”.ti evorP  ?haey
esucxE“	     ”.uoy sekil ehs kniht I spleh ti fI“
”.sdrawretfa em htiw emit emos sdneps yllausu eh dna semit fo ytnelp rennid evah eW
.ytlayol kcap rof nwonk erew yeht nosaer a saw ereht tub
,ralupop syawla saw htoob renroc eht elihW
elzzum reh ot pu detaolf allinav dna tunlezah mraW
,esnes cimonoce edam dah ti tub
.redro s’sivaD eraperp ot nageb dna puc a tuo tes ehs
.ylimaf ym teem ot ydaer ton s’eh esuaceb s’ti esoppus I“  .deggurhs
”,uoy ekil yug a evol dluow ohw ereht tuo seidal fo tol a era ereht wonk I
,namow tnednepedni na saw haraS rehtom
.mret eht saw pu gnikcahS
noows ot dedneterp ylleK
rehtegot gnivil erew yeht erehw ecalp egnarts a ni erew yehT
.rehtorb gib a sa gniksa osla saw eh tub
.elbat eht ot txen doots ehs sa
,noitcepsni pans a rof ydaer syawlA
.flesreh dlot dah ehs tahw s’taht tsael ta
ehS	      .deilper ycuL ”,ti no
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
gnitiaW	     .otatop fo setib neewteb ni derewsna flow eht ”,taht ees nac
.retsis sih neht dna
stnemertuocca detaler dna recuas eht htiw nwod gum eht tes ehs ylsseltroffE
,kcolc’o neves yltcaxe ta thgin yadnuS yreve rennid rof emit edam syawla dna
namow evitcartta ehtil ehT
ni flesreh delkcub ehS
.dekrow ehs sa secnalg fo elpuoc a elots ycuL
,yeH“	     .deilper ycuL ”,huh
,ycuL ot cisum ekil dednuos syawla ffats gnikooc eht fo stroffe ehT
.enohp llec reh tuo dellup dna deggurhs ycuL
”,elbazingocernu oot eb t’now ehs
”,ti ekil uoy woh tsuJ
.triks gnihctam dna tekcaj yerg krad a htiw gnola ,esuolb etihw a erow ycuL gninrom
.tros eht fo gnihtyna ro degagne nettog t’ndah yeht tub
.noitautis eht emarf ot yaw retteb a dekcal ehs tub
.drah yrev yrt ot evah d’uoy tbuod I
pis tset a gnikaT
sa dias ehs ”,orb ,dab ti tog uoY“  .dekrims
.ylleK deman saw eeffoc reh thguorb dah ohw namow ehT
.syadiloh eht sdrawot neppah ot dednet ylno hcihw
.pu deklaw ssertiaw eht sa tnemom a rof puc eeffoc eht dniheb ecaf reh dih ehS
s’erehT“	      ”.enif er’ew ,yllaer tuB
seod ehs sselnu tub
”?tol a rehto hcae ees t’nod uoy dna tnemtrapa na erahs syug
ycuL	     .deksa eh ”?su htiw tsafkaerb ot emoc reven s’eh emoc woh
”,enaKcM sivaD ,flow doog a
gnicitoN	     .wap rehto reh no hctaw revlis a saw
.dne eht no eno eht eb ot deneppah syawla
.ruf reh ot tnecca ecin a edivorp ot hguone tnereffid tsuj tub roloc ni ralimis saw tI
I“	      ”.rehtegot kcits s’enaKcM eW
.xelA“	     ”?eman reh s’tahW“
ycuL	      ”.drow eht yas tsuj uoy ,ti fo erac ekat ll’taht stellub fo lluf enizagam a dna levohs a tog ev’I ekil t’nod uoy yaw a ni uoy no wap a stup eh fI“  .dias eh ”,ton epoh
riehT	      .dednim enoyna taht ton
,seitinaforp erew detcepsus ylgnorts ehs tahw fo gnilbmum fo tib a retfa tub
a htiw pu dekool eh enog saw ehs ecnO
.noh ,eeffoc ruoy
?enoemos teem ot ekil thgim ehs ebyam kniht uoy t’noD“
,htoob etirovaf reh sdrawot dekool eh sa mra sih rednu dekcut yltaen saw tah siH
sreviR neruaL yb ”eeffoC gninroM“
.ekacnap erom emos gnitae ,dias ycuL ”,esruoc
.ylkciuq gninrael s’ehs tub decneirepxeni ytterp s’ehS
htoob eht sdrawot revo dellorts eH
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ereht no saw enon erus gnikam yb melborp eht evomer ot deirt ehs os
,ycuL ot noitaripsni na neeb syawla dah ecneiliser reH
,nepo saw ti gnieeS
.gniddik saw ehs raelc saw ti hguoht
rehtom rieht ot esolc ylemertxe sselehtreven erew ycuL dna sivaD
,seY“	     .deksa ehs ”?uoy pleh I
.nrettap gnitanretla na ni senots raelc dna eulb htiw
ekiL“	     .deilper ehs ”,ekacfeeb a er’uoy taht kniht
.nwod ti gnittes dna
htaerb peed a koot ehs muirta eht morf edisni ylluf gnippetS
.pets reh ni tlit a yldrah htiw revo dedilg ehs sa eeffoc eht ekil wolf ot demees
fI“	     ”.tuoba gniyrrow htrow gnihton s’erehT
sivaD	     ”?oge ruoy etalfni yleslaf d’I kniht uoY“  .deilper ycuL
enohp sih ta dekool
.gge na eta ehs emit yna kloy ynnur taht devol ehS
.noitcartsid yratnemom eht detaicerppa
,nooM eulB fo rohtua dna
.swodniw eht fo lla tsniaga shtoob dna rab eht gnola gnitaes dah s’ykcuL ,renid lacipyt
?stnaw eh tahw swonk ohw yug a dna ,mrofinu ni nam
ylraelC	     ”?dneirflrig a teg ot gniog uoy era nehW“
.sloots eht no gnitiaw sremotsuc eht ot tsafkaerb gniretaw htuom rehtona dereviled ssertiaw eht sa retnuoc eht no deknilc setalP
”.erus m’I ,yltrohs gnola eb lliw
ecaf ytuop tseb reh ni eugnot reh tuo kcuts
.ssertiaw eht langis ot wap sih desiar dna
ehT	      .ssenisub ni ti tpek ohw slacol eht rof tops tsafkaerb llaw eht ni eloh ralupop a saw ti tub
.riap eht devres yllaitini dah ohw namow eht naht eno tnereffid a saw ssertiaw sihT
er’uoY“	     .dias ehs ”,uoy knahT“
.ecaf sih fo tnorf ni sregnif reh deppans
,esuoh lluf a saw ti sselnu reh rof nepo ti tpek yllacipyt renwo eht taht hguone gnol ereh gniog neeb dah ehs
I“	     ”.uoy morf taht ekil gnihtemos peek t’ndluow I ,em tsurT“
.elbat eht no nwod ecaf decalp ehs hcihw tekcit rieht htiw denruter
”,dad ecnis enoyna detad reven s’ehs taht tsuj s’tI
saw sihT         .tsenrae ni
uoY“	      ”.hcuot ni peek ew tub
sivaD	     .sekacnap reh fo slufkrof wef a eta ycuL
ycuL	        ”?eeffoc elbirret evlovni yrtnallag did nehw ecniS“
.elzzum reh fo tnorf ni eceip eht gnidloh
ot ytiliba tnerappa s’rehtorb redlo reh htiw desserpmi syawla saw ycuL
I“	     .deksa eh ”?ohw
”.purys yrrebpsar htiw sekacnap tunlaw dna yrrebeulb fo redro lausu ym evah lliw I kniht I
”,niaga drow taht
.rood eht denepo ehs tnemom eht srae s’ycuL dellif syawla
ll’I“	      .sivaD ot gninrut
.tnemom eht ta erew nhoJ dna ehs yltcaxe tahw wonk t’ndid ehs hturt nI
.ecaf sih no noisserpxe yrw a htiw niaga eeffoc eht detsat sivaD
,elyts dna roloc rof detanidrooc sehtolc rieht htiw redro tcefrep ni ruf rieht htiw deffioc yltcefrep eb ot detcepxe syawla erew seidaL
.noitseuq txen reh desop ehs
.deilper sivaD ”?esle
tuohtiW	     .noitcerid reh ni walc a dekop eH
.dnopser ot ton esohc eh hguoht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.laem eht fo samora eht gnilahni fo wohs gib a edam ehs ekacnap eht ot pu thgir eson reh gnisserP
,tops eht no
.yad s’ycuL fo trats laiciffo eht delangis syawla ereh lavirra reH
retnuoc eht dniheb kcab gniklaW
I“	      ”.gniht ylimaf a si tsafkaerb taht skniht tsuj nhoJ kniht I“
tub ecalp reh morf klaw etunim evif a ylno saw tI
,eruS“	     .deksa eh ”?tsafkaerb ym htiw og ot eeffoc fo puc a teg I naC  .nac uoy
stekcap reneteews dna remaerc eht ta nwod derats ycuL sA
er’uoY“	      .elbatalap ti ekam ot troffe na ni egareveb gnidneffo eht otni remaerc emos dna ragus fo stekcap evif deruop flow elam ehT
revO“	     .deksa ssertiaw eht
.on semit dnasuoht A  .oN“
diuqil nworb eht ta decnalg eh nwod
”?ekil uoy dluow tahw
tsuJ“	     ”?yadot yad gib a toG“
romuh doog ni ti koot
”.evol ni m’I kniht I
,noitseuq eht gnitcepxe ton
yrroS“	     .noitom diulf elgnis a ni edis etisoppo eht otni gnilttes
.elbat eht rednu sgel reh dessorc
.daeh sih koohs
,citcat llats a fo tib a saw ti wenk ydaerla eh reh dlot rehtorb reh morf kool ehT
.esuoh eht fo tuo devom dah ycuL dna sivaD ecnis dah ehs sa
yletal rehto hcae fo tol elohw a nees t’nevah ew os I ma os dna tol a gnikrow s’eH“
.etalp eht no deird yeht nehw meht naelc ot gnivah diova ot yaw siht sgge reh tae dluow dna buc a saw ehs nehw detrats lla tI  .ekorb ti erofeb htuom reh ni kloy elohw eht teg neht dna tsrif setihw eht tae ot yrt syawla dluow ycuL
sivaD	      ”.gniog teg retteb d’eW“
.reh no seye sih tpek eh
.rewsna non tseb reh gnidivorp
.gniht fo tros taht ta erew yeht doog woh ycuL dnimer ot meht thguorb ylpmis yeht fi derednow ehs
.wap ni eeffoc reh htiw dehcaorppa ssertiaw terref
.tnemom a rof daeh sih detlit
ehT	     .retnuoc eht dniheb ffo derepmacs ehs ,taht htiW
.og uoy ereH“  .dias eh
sivaD	     .dap redro na tuo deppihw ehS
ycuL	     ”.su morf tnemegaruocne emos sdeen tsuj ehs ebyaM
yllufepoH“	     ”.sraey rof ereh neeb s’ehs ekil eb ll’tI
ycuL	     ”.ti evresed yeht ,su ot doog ytterp er’yehT“
.eivom eht nees ,koob eht daer ev’I“
naC“	      .rehtorb reh sdrawot yldneirf yllaicepse demees ehs deton ycuL
.sekacnap fo lufkrof rehtona gnitae yb sdnoces lanoitidda wef a flesreh yub ot detpmetta ycuL
,oN“	      .suoitcefni dnuof ycuL msaisuhtne na htiw deksa ehs ”?slaiceps eht raeh ot ekil uoy dluoW
.retteb tol a eb lliw eeffoc txen ruoy esimorp I
,purys artxe thguorb syawla ssertiaw eht hguohT
.unem eht reh dednah ehS
.mih sdrawot derutseg ylpmis ehs doof fo etib reh morf pu gnikool
,tol gnikrap eht ot edistuo rehtorb reh dewollof
er’eW“	      .level txen eht ot ti evom noos dluow eh depoh ehs
esroW“	     .deksa ycuL ”?huh
mih txet ot egru eht gnitsiseR
.feiler ni tsehc reh dehcuot ssertiaw enilef eht sa dekrims
”,ti no rettub htiw tsaot fo eceip a dna
.diuqil suoiretsym eht fo ffins eltneg a koot eh sa
.gnitrofmoc ti dnuof ehs tub
”.sebiv on erew erehT  ?sebiv tahW
.detsetorp eh ”,yracs ton
.gnikool ereht tuo eb d’ehs efil reh ni nam a detnaw ehs fi tub ,os
sivaD	     ”?em ekil elpoep rof efas ytic eht gnikam fo yad rehtona rof ydaer uoy era ,rehtorb gib oS“
I“	     ”.semitemos ylenol teg tsum ehS“  .dettimda sivaD
.dias eh ”,era uoy thgiR“
.dias ehs ”,ysae
”?emosdnah m’I kniht
”.dalcnori sti ,klat ot em ecrof t’nac
ycuL	     .deil eh ”,doog s’tI“
”.ydaer er’uoy nehw redro ruoy ekat ot kcab thgir eb ll’I  .emoclew
.daeh sih koohs
”,reh tuoba yrrow semitemos
”.demees ti os ro ,ysub ytterp saw ehs tub ,dnekeew siht reh dellac I“	     .deksa eh
”.lio rotom naht
A“	     .noitatiseh tuohtiw dias eh
.sraluger eb ot dekool renid eht gnillif elpoep eht fo ytirojam
,srennid lanoitidda ni tluser netfo dluow hcihw
gnikooL	      ”.eeffoc taht gniknird llits er’uoY“
”.reh gnieb yppah tsuj s’ehs elbissop yleritne s’tI
.rewsna reh etalumrof ot etunim a reh evig dluow ti tub ,gnol rof sivaD yaled ton dluow doof eht wenk ehS
,suoiciled saw doof ehT
.nosaes taht noihsaf ni eb ot detcepxe erew yeht seohs erow eno fi dna
.htaed s’rehtaf rieht retfa enola spup owt reh desiar gnivah
krow dah ehs nehw yrossecca rehto ylno reH
liat eht ni niap a syawla saw deifidilos dah taht sgge gnivomeR
ytic eht ni sesuoh eeffoc ycnaf eht fo emos sa snoitpo ynam sa evah ton did ecalp siht elihW  .tcefrep
.esnopser ni kool ytsan a ycuL tohs eh recuas eht no nwod kcab gum eht gnittuP
”?gninrom siht uoy gninioj rehtorb ruoy sI“	      ”.uoy knahT“
epytoerets flow a saw ti spahreP
eeffoc reh nettog dah ssertiaw eht taht desirprus lla ta ton saw ehs
elihW	     .meht fo yna gnitarutas tuohtiw eceip
etirovaf s’ycuL
htoob rieht morF
.tellaw sih fo tuo sllib wef a gnihsif ,dias sivaD
,soidutS ecnecsedirI fo sreviR neruaL yb ”eeffoC gninroM“
.gnikrow dna ,yppah ,yhtlaeh er’eW
elihw a rof yako saw taht elihw dna
sivaD	     ”.tuo thgir eb ll’ti dna uoy rof ni tup taht teg ll’I“
.knird gnidneffo eht fo pis rehtona koot eH
,dias ycuL ”,enif
noicipsus emos htiw ti dedrager dna puc eht koot ylsuoituac sivaD	     ”.yrroS“
ecalp eht fo ytiralupop eht ot kaeps ot demees revonrut fo tol a evah t’ndid ecalp siht taht tcaf ehT
.esle enoyna gnitruh t’nsaw ti sa gnol sa did uoy tahw erac t’ndid sgnieb tneitnes nredom tsoM
.reh ezingocer neve t’now uoy skeew wef a nI
m’I“	     ”.sredro eeffoc eht htiw ereh tnaw uoy tahw wonk ot mees tsuj yeht yllausU
.ti htrow llew saw ti
.puc tcefrep eht eraperp dna doom reh etapicitna ot demees syawla yeht
toG“	      .doohtluda otni deirrac dah ehs kriuq a saw ti tub
fO“	     ”?edis eht no gge deirf a dna tsaot fo eceip a teg I naC“
.riap eht fo tnorf ni elbat eht no nwod ti gnittes ,redro rieht htiw denruter ssertiaw ehT
”.enihcam eht krow ot woh wonk I kniht I“
.dehgis dna ecaf reh fo tuo riah ednolb reh dehsurb sseflow ehT	     .deilper eh
deb ot ti erow rehtorb reh denigami semitemos ehs
.ssendoog knaht ,hO“
ebyaM“	     .tuo detniop sivaD
,rac eht detrats sivaD sa wodniw eht tuo derats dna
,haeY“	     ”?od uoy emit emas eht krow evah eh t’nseoD“
,enola devil rehtom reH
,pis egral rehtona koot sivaD  ”.uoy knahT
,syadhtrib s’rehtom rieht dna syadiloh gnieb snoitpecxe ylno eht
tsaot reh fo etib a koot
.enohp reh ta dekool ehs
gnilahnI	      .eson reh otni tfaw doof eht fo sllems eht gnittel
.noitca rof ydaer kool syawla
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.deilper sivaD ”,os yas uoy
tub boj ysub a dah eh wenk ehS  .etal saw sivaD
.ettal allinav ruoy depmoc I“
ycuL	     .noitcefrep etulosba ot dekooc sredro rieht fo htob htiw
:yojne esaelP  .ytiniffaruF no
.reh fo thgis eht ta yoj htiw gninediw seye sih
.retsis ruoy m’I tub ,yllanosrep ton
,sivaD morf kool rehtona reh denrae tnemmoc reh hguoht nevE
.redneg rieht fo tifeneb yb ylpmis
.niart eht dniheb kcuts tog I tpecxe renoos ereh neeb ev’dluow I“
.ciffart otni nar
devil trohs eht deyojne ehs tnemom a rof regnil meht gnitteL
pu kcip dluoc sesnes enipul denut ylenif reh
hcae rovalf ot tnuoma thgir eht tsuj htiw ekacnap fo seceip eht detaoc purys gninetsilg der ehT
.dekrims dna hteet sih revo eugnot sih nar
,noitinifed raelc a dekcal yltnerruc pihsnoitaler eht ,llitS
,lleW“	     ”.spihsnoitaler dna krow gnixim ,aedi doog a toN“
.retaw ytrid delbmeser fo dnik taht
,saw eh erehw mih gniksa
sivaD	      ”.ecrof eht no nemow fo stol era erehT“
”.elzzum taht nottub d’I krow ot klaw ot tnaw uoy sselnu
ehS	      .krow ot ecalp a dna yretae na sa htob
.thgiarts nam eht gnittes htiw seussi on evah dluow sivaD
,krow syawla t’ndid tI
,sreviR neruaL yb ”eeffoC gninroM“
I“	     ”.ecnatsid ruo peek ot deen tsuj ew
.gniziteppa os dekool syawla serutcip ehT
uoY“	      ”.pu eno taht kool ot evah thgim I  ?yllaer hO“
,teews ,emosdnah er’uoy ,lleW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.troffe eht ekam dluohs uoy
detnaw ehs tahw wenk ydaerla ehs hguoht
.og ot ydaer nep dna dap redro reh htiw denruter ssertiaw eht
s’ereH“	     .elims yldneirf a dereffo dna
.eeffoc eht deffins dna delims ehS
.dias ehs ”,htfif eht daelp
ti tuoba klat nac ew neht enoemos reh dnif ot su sksa mom fI
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
elims eslaf a no gniworht erofeb decamirg eh pis a gnikaT
.mih ediseb ti decalp dna tah sih ffo koot eH  ”.tsafkaerb
uoY“	     ”.mrofinu a ni doog yllaer kool uoy noitnem ot ton ,layol
.nwo sti no yllarutan
rewsna evitagen yna edivorp ot ehs ereW
.deilper ehs ”,setunim wef a
?evah uoy ll’tahw ,yawynA
ohW“	     .deksa ycuL ”?nhoJ
,ynnur artxe ,sgge owt ,seotatop fo edis a htiw kaets a evah
nevE	      .eeffoc fo puc a rof wap reh pu dleh dna nwod tas ehs
.wap sih fo erutseg a htiw ssertiaw a nwod deggalf sivaD	      ”.edoc
”?uoy dluow ,taht fo elttil a reh eviG
,eeffoc sih gniknird saw eh litnu
oS“	     ”.etad a no og ot krow htiw ysub oot neeb ev’I“
uoY“	     .erats gniveilebsid a htiw reh dexif eH  ”?em
,edirts htooms lausu sih htiw
gnimoC“	     .dias eh ”,esaelp uoy fi ,ettal allinav a em gnirb tsuj ,neht
.deilper ylleK ”,ti
”?suovren uoY  .erus
.krof sih htiw reh ta detniop
diD“	     ”?thgir ,pit rallod ytnewt a reh evag uoy ezilaer od uoY“
”,pu reh gnixif fo gnikniht ton er’uoy epoh
”,sivaD em llac
reh htiw devil regnol on nerdlihc reh taht tcaf eht etipseD
.eeffoc cisab eht redro dluoc uoy syaw tnereffid fo tnuoma evisserpmi na dah sselehtreven yeht
,seeffoc ycnaf gnikam ni ecneirepxe fo laed taerg a evah ton did ehs raelc saw tI
.nwot fo sedis etisoppo no krow eW“	     .deksa eh
ycuL	      .detaeper sivaD ”,xelA“	      ”.xelA“
gniht emas eht redro syawla ton did ycuL taht tcaf eht etipsed teY
tseretni lausac tsuj saw ti wenk ycuL  .rewsna fo tros emos tog eh litnu
.rac lortap sih fo edis regnessap eht no gnippots
.eurt t’nsaw taht wenk ehs hguoht
.thgiled htiw revihs yliratnulovni ot reh gnisuac
kaets sih decils sivaD
.edoc gnilbis eht fo trap s’tI
.sesnes eht ot suoiciled
.noitanitsed yliad reh ot tuo gnidaeh dna desserd gnitteg erofeb rewohs a ekat dna esir dluow ehs gninrom yrevE