.dekil eh cisum tahw mih ksa ot emac yehT
.raeb gnikluh dna esnetni na ,tsigoloisehtseana eht ot mih decudortni yehT
”fO gninroM“ saw sihT
.denetfos nirg s’viL
dnah sih fo kcab eht devahs yehT
”.dnim ruoy egnahc ot uoy rof kcab emoc yeht litnu evah uoy uoy llet ot em dlot yehT“
tneserp-repyh ekilmaerd eht litnu ,emit a ta eno
”.stun og d’I kniht I ,eromyna ti tuoba klat uoy ot netsil ot dah I fI
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.yawllah suomynona na nwod mih ksihw ot emac yehT
— teid ylno sdiulf tcirts siht no
,traeH eht fo ssendliW A noitcelloc reh morf si yrots s’yadoT
.edarap a ni dnuof eb ot
,smeop ,seirots dnif nac uoy erehw ,kni.oykam ta elbaliava si gnitirw reH .kni.oykam.ssendliw
.nwog eht htaeneb stsaerb sih revo sdnah yldnips deppuc eH ”.thgiR“
.gnitcepxe saw eh tahw ekil gnihton moor a ,RO eht otni mih leehw ot emac yehT
.rekihhctih flowerew
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.yls saw nirg s’flow redlo ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sdnah rieht ni ylurt saw eh neht dnA
.ecalp ni enil VI eht tog dna
.tuohs a syawla ton si yrotciV
.tuo lla mih deitpme perp yregrus eht sa
.esrun gnikool-tneiciffe na htiw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”?yas yeht tahw htiw gnola og dna og tel si
moorhtab eht dna
,ynit leef mih edam tnemrag ehT
.mih ot gnorw tlef ngis eht yhw trapa kcip ot gniyrt
gnirud peels ot ytilibani etelpmoc eht dna
,tnerrohba doof fo thguoht eht edam sevren dna sevitaxal eht fo noitanibmoc emos tub
”.ssa ruoy kcik d’I ,gniog peek t’ndid uoy fi meht dlot I“
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.daeh sih edisni ylbatrofmocnu gnidworc erew gninaem dna sdrow taht esirprus on saw ti dna
.nwog latipsoh a otni dna sehtolc sih fo tuo deppirts flow gnuoy eht erehw
.reh fo tseb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
.oot ,stun og ylbaborp d’I“ .gnuoy
,noitanimreted tnelis eht ni
dnaltroP ot evird ruoh xis eht ni ddA
.gniylf tuoba yas uoy tahw sleef tI“
.enilno eerf rof daer ro esahcrup ot skoob dna
?gnihtyna eh saW ?eh saW
.viL htiw enola mih tfel yeht neht dnA
ksam negyxo na mih evig ot emac yehT
.eirever sih fo tuo flesmih koohs eH ”?ydaer uoY ?xelA“
.ecaf sih revo dloh ot
,ytilibisnopser s’esle enoemos
,erofeb thgin eht
.eson s’xelA ni kciht gnignah setisoppo fo tnecs eht tfel ’yregrus yrotalubma‘ esarhp eht tuoba gnihtemoS
.noegrus eht htiw sdnah ekahs mih tel yehT
”fO gninroM“   yojne esaelP
”.taht ekil s’tI“ .deddon viL
— gninrom siht sdem sih htiw retaw fo pis a tub gnihton neht dna
.yako-ton leef t’ndid eh tub ,yako leef t’ndid eH
,moor po-erp eht ot kcab mih del yehT ”.haeY“
ylno ton si edirP
si yrots s’yadoT dna
yrgnuh ylbidercni eb dluow eh taht ,tsrif ta ,thguoht dah eH
od ot evah uoy lla dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.raey a tsomla rof pots-non yregrus siht tuoba gniklat neeb ev’uoY“
eno tsal yrev eht fo
,tnemom elbakramernu hcae gnivil fo ssenisub yad-yb-yad eht ni
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”fO gninroM“
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
ylneddus si gnihtyreve neht dna
eht sa detardyh yats ot flesmih ecrof ot dah eh dna
.gninrom worromot ot pu dda yllanif lla yeht erofeb
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,ybbol eht ni gnittis ,saw eh ereh tey dna ,noromyxo na yllautca t’nsaw ylniatrec tI
.ssendliw ta dnif nac uoy hcihw
.’sevren sih rof‘ ekat ot llip a mih evag yehT
.yawa mih ekat ot emac yeht neht dnA ”.wonk I“
,syawla sa tnaidar ,ereht gnidnats saw viL
deb ro hcuoc eht neewteb htrof dna kcab gninnur syad owt tsal eht tneps dah eH
.mih no srednow sti dekrow etartic muisengam
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dna
,edirP yppaH
.deb eht fo egde eht no gnittis ,deddon eH ”?xelA ,yako uoY“
”?taht s’yhW“ .dehgual xelA
,ytiruces tsap teg uoy woH
,ecneitap fo stnemom teiuq eht ni tneserp hcum sa tsuj si hpmuirT
”.me‘ fo dir eb ot ecin os eb ll’tI