.noitseuq a deksa sÕeh sa leviws srae siH
.ni smooz aremac eht sa hgis A Ó.haey É oS Õ.srelwohÔ
.tib a gnixelf ,trihs sih ffo sekat ynnoL
aremac eht gnivig ,syas ynnoL
.KAERB LAICREMMOC .kcalb ot tuC
.elzzum reh pu sessalg reh gnihsup ylsuoicsnoc-fles ,elggig yhs A
.ytnoM revo rewot yllausiv ot reh gniwolla ,pu sgnur owt
É tsuJ .ereht ni sriahc dna elbat on sÕereht esuaceb sÕti ,smaercs raeh uoy fIÒ
.moor ot moor sevor aremac ehT .yawllah ot tuC
! É taht deen tÕnod uoYÒ
moor eulb a tnemelpmoc roloc ot tog I ffuts dlog dna wolley taht lla sseug I ,naem I É lleWÒ
esuoh rehtona oTÒ
.nommoc ni evah ew erom tsuJ
!hguoht ,deirrow toNÒ
,uoYÒ .ylniatrecnu sesuap eH
Ó?gnicar enord ton tub scipmylO eht ni gniklaw deeps sÕerehTÒ
htiw og ot dediced  É
.neercs eht no sraeppa elpuoc arabypac decaf-enots a fo egami nA
Ó.pu ti dehctiws IÒ Ó É ÕneriS
,haey ,haH !ekalB
!esuoH ruoY esuoM fo edosipe wen gniticxe rehtona rof yadsendeW txen ni enuT
!eciffo eht revo lla gniddehs sÕehS .krow ta allihcnihc taht saw tIÒ
Ó.rocŽd eht htiw flesruoy nrecnoc tsuJÒ
,sriahc dna elbat nehctik wen eht gnihsilop dna gnignarra ,yeldirF
Ó.ecno boj laer a deirt IÒ
.sworb sih gnilggaw
.taht gniod syawla erÕyehTÒ
:ekalB - riahc weivretnI
.orb latot a sÕeHÒ
.htuom sih morf gnittuj hteetkcub ,slwocs ynnoL Ó.ssa na
?ereh tuo uoy sgnirb tahw É hu ,oSÒ
.syas enilef eht Ó,ekalB sÕeman yMÒ
.sdneirf tnedor detrossa htiw hcrop a no semag drac gniyalp si lerriuqs der a ,thgiliwt tA          .KAERB LAICREMMOC
Ó.peels fo naeco na ni gninword sÕeh ekil leef nac eH
?sdnamed tnagele reh yfsitas yeht naC
,nat hsiyarg a ,nwaf ydnas
,dren YID dna tsimitpo lanrete nA
Ó?mih nrut annog erÕuoy
.moor siht rof eulb naeco ,thgirb a no ni gniorez ydaerla si ehS
.kool Õtuoba gniklat eh si tahwÔ
Ó!yadsendeW ytilaer RUOY sÕti ,thginot ,tuBÒ Ó!Õti ees tsum
Ó.ytisoiruc fo tuo É gniksa tsuj ,wonkÕYÒ
Ó?dneirflrig eht sÕerehW
,82 ega ,raguoc a mÕIÒ
,stnemal recnuonna nA
.gnipacsdnal dna stnalp htiw doog eb dÕI kniht tÕndluow uoY
,mugelbbub ,tnim ni semoC
Ó.maet nosrep-evif a htiw melborp eht sÕtahTÒ
!wohs eht dna ,su fo tser eht sevol eh wonk I
.elcric a ni snrut ytnoM Ó?anidE ,roloc
Õ.edutittarÔ htiW
.tnemeticxe htiw nediw seye eulb siH Ó.mM .kaew adniKÒ
É won moordeb eht gniod ,moor gnivil dna moor gninid eht did eW
Ó.kcos-liat a ffo llup ot
rapÔ ,ti decnuonorp eh sa ,rO .ytrap ot sekil eh syas ekalB .sgnirehtag roodtuo evah ot ecaps hguone evael ot deeNÒ
.moor rehtona ot tuC
.elbakatsimnu si sserttam gnicnuob a fo gnikaerc ehT Ó!ylliB
,smialcorp recnuonna wollem A
eht era tahW !taht ekil tsuJ
Ó.neerg tserof elbon yrev A
É nees eb ot erehwon era ,elihwnaem ,anidE dna sgnilliB
,dias dna spih sih no swap sih tup esuom esuoh ehT
daeh sÕytnoM seips dna snrut aremac ehT
,reddal a no si anidE
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil erÕuoY
erÕuoy snaem tsuj tIÒ
.ylteiuq syas ytnoM Ó,eulb no
.KAERB LAICREMMOC
.ruf dehs htiw derevoc steehs etihw ta nwod gnikool ,deb fo tuo sllor allihcnihc elamef A
Ó,noitanigami fo kcal hcuSÒ
Ó?esolc oot si esolc woh tub
:ytnoM Ð riahC weivretnI
?namrehsif eci na ekil kool I oDÒ .sesuap eH Ó.oN
Ó,kcab eht ni É seldeen enip yb
,erutinruf gnidulcni ,dehsinif si moor ÕneergÔ ehT
,secamirg lerriuqs ehT
.tnempiuqe dna sloot nedrag gnignarra sÕeh erehw ,egarag eht ot stuc neht aremaC
Ð riahC weivretnI Ó!ma I ereh tuB
.htam sih seifirev yllatnem eh sa gnihcnurcs ecaf
Ó.ereh tnega eerf eurt ylno eht mÕI .emit yna ta
,gnihctiwt ylbisiv
sseug tuB .ti od reven dÕyeht tub ,ti tuoba klat yeht ,hO
.gniod sÕehs tahw spots anidE Ó?VT ruoYÒ
.htuom rieht ni flah ni skaerb yltnatsni hcihw ,kcits doow a no wang ot seog lerriuqs ehT
Ó.retfa mÕI tahw sÕtahT !emosewAÒ
.taoc retniw rieht htaenrednu liat elisneherp rieht ffuts ot niav ni gniyrt ,wons eht ni pots sub a ta srevihs esuom tsevrah A Ó É siht rO
esiryks cirotsih a tisiv ecim nwot ehT
.ssalg sih pord ot mih gnisuac tsomla ,aremac ffo
.ollecitnoM .esuom esuoh yerg-eulb A
.ylteiuq sksa esuom reppohssarg eht
,oSÒ .aremac eht ta
ylevitroppus si ohw ,yeldirF sllet ytnoM
.ynnoL si ,gnipacsdnal fo egrahc ni ,puorg eht fo rebmem htfif ehT
.tuo stniop sgnilliB
Õgnithgil doomÔ sa selbuod ti ,oslA
!haey ,)PEELB(Ò .tsif a spmup eh
Ó É retnuoc a dna sloots rab
.nwo ym no ti nesohc evÕdluow I ,wonkÕy É tuBÒ
sAÔ Õ.gnimrahc yldriewÔ ti gnillac era scitirCÒ
Ó.mih ni sees anidE tahw sÕtaht sseug IÒ
.STIDERC DNE NIGEB
.sehctaws tniap reh ezinagro ot gniunitnoc ,sksa anidE
Ó.heH !gnihtyna ro mih sserpmi ot gniyrt mÕI ekil ton sÕtI .yllautnevE
Ó.hsitef surtic a sah eh ekil kool tsuj llÕtIÒ
Ó?em sekil eh kniht uoy oDÒ
,lennahc emas eht no lla meht evah I fi dnA
Ó.peels emos teg ,hctiBÒ
.scinahcem ykculp fo maet ruo yb sdor toh otni denrut teg srac teerts Õstnatsetnoc ykcul
:yeldirF Ð riahC weivretnI
.doof fo slufhtuom neewteb ,sksa eh
Ó,eiteews ,uoy tcetorp llÕIÒ
Ó?uoy ot deneppah siht saHÒ
,kcits wehc-oR a no wang yeht sa aremac eht ot pu sbmuht a sevig lerriuqs ehT
.tneserp lla era ecim ruof rehto ehT
.og eht no syawla ylgnimees
.elbissop sa yletilop sa ,seilper anidE
.etsatretfa rettib taht fo enoN
.ti ot thgir steg dna taorht sih sraelc ytnoM
spih reh no swap reh stup ehS
Ó É litnu trats neve tÕnac IÒ .sdnimer ytnoM
wohs tih gninniw-drawa eht fo edosipe wen-lla na sÕtiÒ
yna gnitnalp htiw yawa teg nac ew kniht tÕnod I
Ó?ecneirepxe morf taht wonk uoy dnAÒ Ó.amarD ?esuoM
emit yxes eb llÕti neht
.yzarc htob erÕyehT
Ó.ciffart syawla sÕerehTÒ
.gnikaeuqs ecim eht raeh llits nac eH .gnikcoc srae
Ó?ti tÕnsi ,gnikniht orb lacipyt sÕti ,lleWÒ Ó!ssenluftser dna
.gniliec eht ta gnirats ,htaerb a tuo swolb yeldirF detarepsaxe nA
.esuoh fo edistuo ot tuC
.yaw sih sklaw ekalB ,ynnoL gnieeS
,moor ytpme na ni gnidnats ekalB ot stuc lausiv ehT
Ó É hOÒ Õ.onÔ serutseg namaremac ehT Ó?ereh tuo
.hguoht ,seert gib
,seenk sih no si ynnoL .dray tnorF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.erom rof gnitiaw ,worb a sesiar ytnoM
trihs-t gnittif-thgit a ni enilef derruf-ydnas ,ralucsum a swollof aremac A
.regnif sselruf ,elgnis a fo walc eht htiw kcab dna smra eht secart eH
moor siht rof rocŽd eht lla
Ó,thgiarts sÕeHÒ Ó.did eHÒ
,thgin eht fo elddim eht ni retaw fo ssalg a rof pu gnitteg erÕuoy fi esuaceb knis a evoba sthgil elbammid referp I ,woN !haH ?thgir ,ti tuohtiw gnihtyna ees tÕnac uoy ,naem I
,anidE Ó?roloc a egieb sIÒ
a htiw noisnet lauxes eht tuc dluoc uoYÒ :yeldirF
,siht tuoba wonk uoy did É diDÒ
Ó.egnulp eht koot I ,oS
.sessalg reh stsujda ehS
Ó?wonkÕy ,sllaw eht fo roloc eht tuohtiw gnihton sÕti É naem I ,lleWÒ
Ó?naem I tahw wonkÕy ,deppiuqe ton sÕti nehw revo seidal eht etivni ot draH .krow emos sdeeN
,swehc-oR htiw ecaep ni wanG
:anidE Ð riahC weivretnI
,dnuorgkcab eht ni nees eb nac eH
Ó!retaw toh ni syawla era ohw
.yawevird a pu sllorts eh sa
.nihtiw rucco tnemirrem dna rettahC
Ó?esiwrehto ereh eb llits eh dluow yhW
Ó?enord ym ylf annaw ,ebab ,yeHÒ
.egarag eht sretne eh sa syas ekalB Ó!nam ,dray
Ð riahC weivretnI .eye-edis emos
Ó,ÕneriS keerGÔ naht retteb skool ÕeniP reveroFÔ kniht IÒ
Ó É em ni detseretni eb tÕndluow si ti reveohw erus mÕIÒ
:ytnoM Ð riahC weivretnI
.stnap sih no ruf eht ot stniop ylsuoicipsus ohw
esuom esuoh ehT Ó?mih rof yrros leef I oDÒ
.cisab ytterp si ecaps
.ylhtooms syas recnuonna eht Ó,orP relloR tlePÒ
.ekalB ot gniklat ,sucof fo tuo
Ó.taes hsulp a sevol yeldirFÒ
.don citsaisuhtne nA  Ó.renroc
.reh dna ekalB neewteb snap-pihw aremac ehT
.neercs eht ssorca pihw ,elamef dna elam ,sliat dekan tnereffid ynam gnirevoc kcos-liat fo snoihsaf ynaM
,knis eht raen steltuo sa raf sa ,won É hu ,tuBÒ
.seunitnoc recnuonna eht
!ysrevortnoc a fo tib a si siht
,nap tniap eht ni rellor reh spid ehS
Ó!taht htiw kcul dooGÒ
.semuf ehcadaeh ffo gnivig si roloc egieb-yllacinhcet-ton eht fi sa
smargorPÔ .VT YRRUCS no ylnOÒ Ó!ediR ruoY taR
É tub ,tac a rednu sevres esuom a taht netfo ton sÕti wonk I .heH ?em tsurt tÕnoD
.pu gnikool ton yb looc ti yalp ot seirt
kniht uoYÒ Ó!)PEELB( debrab a sah eHÒ
Ó!rednerrus I .noiprocs a ton mÕIÒ
.ytrap eht ot gninruter ylkciuq
.elitasrev dna paehc si notuf a ,eruSÒ
.doog sÕtaht ,llew É ees IÒ
alumrof reikcits ,wen ruO
Ó?em rof egarag eht ni kcab snac tniap eseht tup uoy nac ,ytnoMÒ
Ó.sdik ,monev guhc tÕnod :remialcsiDÒ
Ó.sÕyeldirF fo dneirf a ot uoy ecudortni thgim I thguoht IÒ
,ereht ni yffuts tib a gnitteg sÕtIÒ
Ó,Õssa dabÔ snaem ÕorbÔ kniht tÕnod IÒ
.detam era yeldirF dna ytnoMÒ
,epyt nihtiw ,dna epyt yB
debbats gnieb mÕI ekil leef em sekam
Ó?tnaw uoy od tahWÒ
mih htiw sessalg sknilc ytnoM
.ytnoM dna anidE ot tuC
Ó!stsitned-or evif fo tuo ruof yb dednemmoceR .swehc-oR
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
Ó.ti od ecim eht evah llÕI .siht
:yeldirF Ð riahc weivretnI
Ó.snoitseuq suoivbo
.gnihctiwt sreksihw ,selahxe esuom ehT
.seralced lerriuqs eht Ó!seYÒ
.gni-)PEELB( .egnellahCÒ
.syas recnuonna eht
.GNOS EMEHT .kcalb ot tuC
Ó!sedoba drawyaw rieht otni essenif dna elyts gnignirb
.sesimorp ,etam sÕytnoM ,yeldirF
É ot dael neve nac dnAÒ
Ó É afos wen a tog sÕeh nehw gnihtyna
Ó!desuom yllufsseccus esuoh rehtonA
.reddal eht fo edis eht dnuora gnilruc liat elisneherp
!won ,esuoh a rof hguone evaH
Ó!enoyreve rof xoS-T a sÕereht ,seYÒ
Ó!sboj fo tuo eb dÕew ,pu dewohs ew nehw tcefrep erew ti fi ,sediseB
Ó.aremac no ti thguac yeht teb IÒ Ó.gnivas dnoyeb
ecim eht tsap sehsup aremac ehT
.triks trohs yrev a ni nexiv a yb deknalf si ohw
.yldetcejed gnipoord sreksihw ,shgis ynnoL
.hguone noos neppah llÕgnihtemoS
.smra ralucsum sih gnissorc ,syas raguoc eht Ó,nam ,yeHÒ
,traeh sih revo wap sselruf
sihTÒ .nep kni eulb a htiw dapeton a no gnilbbircs ,dray eht hguorht gniklaw ynnoL swohs egatooF
.dooh eht gnisserac ,gnirrup
!taht retfa peels ot kcab teg ot draH
?taht ees uoy diD !emit poT
Ó,thgiRÒ Ó?thgir ,looCÒ Ó É hOÒ
.ytilanoitcnuf tset ot teltuo lacirtcele yreve ot pu seog sgnilliB
.tceffe citamard rof taeb a spiks eH Ó.syug ,yeHÒ
,noitaxaler citsur
Ó.tniap erom deen annog erÕeWÒ .shgis
.ssik a esuom reed eht sevig dna
.detaroced ro dehsinruf emoc tÕndid ti É haeYÒ
.ssenecin sih yalpnwod ot seirt eh sa gurhs A Ó É yeh ,tuB
,knip a gnicalp ,syas esuom elam ypsiw a Ó,hsog ym ,hOÒ
.selgna sehctiws aremac ehT Ó?yhw wonk uoY
.ecnediser eht ruot
noitaxaler setomorp
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
ni VT a deen I ,ekil ,erugif I
.gnivom speek tI .gnihtoN
Ó.noos pu gnimoc si 96 taht siÒ
Ó?huh ,ekalB dna uoy htiw tuo krow tÕndid sgniht ,oSÒ
ssa eht evah tÕnod I
.wap sih no stnuoc ynnoL
Ó?htiw trats ot ereht gnihton sÕereht nehw ÕtiuqÔ uoy nac woHÒ
.ecaf ruoy ni gninihs thgiltops no-lluf a tnaw tÕnod uoy
:ynnoL Ð riahC weivretnI
,repeed yldetareggaxe eciov sih gnikaM
.enod ylraen osla si moordeb eht dna
.edis sÕanidE gnikat ylgnisirprusnu ,syas sgnilliB
Ó?gnihtemos tsniaga ydob ym tup I nehw tuBÒ .esuap A
flesti sdnif tcudorp eht sa hsalf a yb dewollof ,sraeppa tcudorp eht fo egami lufroloc A Ó!swehc-oR yrTÒ
,romuh ta tpmetta sih ot dnopser tÕnseod ynnoL nehW
.morf sÕeh erehw uoy dnimer ot sah syawla ynnoLÒ :ytnoM
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.emoh ,reeraCÒ .snoitnem ynnoL
,raguoc ycnuob eht ot snrut ylkciuq aremac ehT
.niap detareggaxe ni tuo gnikrab
.eciov sih ni tnemtnioppasid eht edih ot elbanu ,syas ynnoL
Ó?draY ?giD ?ti teg ,haHÒ
.dap Õdenoihsaf-dloÔ sÕknuks etilaicos a etavoner ot
Ó?thgir ,siht rof gniyap erÕuoy É hu
,flowcaM boR si sihT
.seunitnoc ynnoL
Ó?thgir É msimehpue a saw taht erus ytterPÒ
.smra sih gnissorc ,riahc eht ni kcab spmuls
,krap deroloc-nmutua na ni wap-ni-wap gniklaw ,esuom dna tar ehT
,taht xif nac yehT
.no sgniog eht tcepsni ot moor eht otni sklaw ,euc no fi sa ,ekalB
eulb fo edahs sihTÒ .snialpxe anidE
.ssa dab ytterp era srelwoh sU
,hOÒ .snaom delffuM !skaeuqS
.aremac eht ot kool detarepsaxe na sevig dna
.afos rallod-dnasuoht ,ywollip a no tuo delwarps esuom reed eht gnidnif ,moor eht sretne sgnilliB Ó.yruxul É tnaw IÒ
ylper tÕnseod ytnoM
,esuoM .T dleiF yb ÓesuoH ruoY esuoMÒ saw sihT      Ó!won tuo dniF
É uoy sekil enoyreve kniht uoYÒ
.trohs rof ytnoM mih llac elpoeP
.evael ot gnisufer
uoYÔ Õ.steg ygrene-wol sa ygrene-hgih
!ssem ssel dnA .nialp ro
.rotarran tneicsinmo eht ot suoivilbo sdneirf rieht ,sdon lerriuqs ehT
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
Ó!od yeht tahw sÕtahT .uoy htiw dnuora gniyalp tsuj ylbaborp saw eH
?eugnot ruoy no sretnilps fo deriTÒ
,rac strops der ycnaf a fo tnorf ni spots eH
.moor ÕeniP reveroFÔ eht ot kcab tuC
É slerriuqs epoletnAÒ
erÕew tahw sÕtahTÒ
.esuom reppohssarg elbmut-dna-hguor A
,ereh ni sllaw eht rof ÕnoissaP deRÔ detseggus ekalBÒ
Ó?oot ,tresed eht morf yeht tÕnera
,tresed eht ni staob tog tÕnod ew esuaCÒ
É rof neeb evah dna tibro sÕrehto hcae ni kcuts era sgnilliB dna anidE
.noitidE tnemtrapA
.snoitidnoc rehtaew lla rof kcos-liat elbatrofmoc-artlu wen ehTÒ
!noitidE tnemtrapA :esuoH ruoY esuoM :hguoht ,txen pU
Ó.secar enord rof tol a levart I dnA
.ytnoM ,ereh tog tsuj eWÒ .syas ytnoM
.drawpu elzzum ytniop sih gnitlit
.sretnuoc anidE Ó!gnithgil reporp
Ó!ssim ,gniht eruSÒ ,syas ytnoM
,sesion gnippals ,kcilS
,detniap ydaerla sah anidE hcihw
si yrots sÕyadoT dna
Ó É desu ehs riahc a ni tas evÕtsum I
?wonkÕy ,taob eht ot kcor ot ekil tÕnod ecim tsoM .em no pu gnignaG
Ó.siht ekil era smoor eht llAÒ
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
?srotavele fo aibohp rieht revo teg yeht lliW
,tuo mih enut ot seirt dna krow ot steg enoyreve sa ,seunitnoc ynnoL
.yeldirF retfa gniog ,sevael esuom esuoh ehT
.enoemos teem I dna
Ó.ssenisub nwo ruoy si ruf ruoYÒ
,yawa skcab ti sa sekahs aremac ehT Ó!)PEELB(Ò Ó!anidE ,ha ,hAÒ .oot
taht htiw É idE htiw evah ot gninaem neeb evÕuoy rennid citnamor taht rof
.strats deef ÕemitemirpÔ krowten eht ,prahs kcolcÕo-thgie tA
,sgnilliB  KAERB FO DNE
Ó!ebiv gnihserfer a hcus saHÒ
,reddal eht no sniamer ehS
.egarag ot tuC Ó.efinkrettub
.moor eht sretne ,oot ,eh sa esuom esuoh eht sksa ehs Ó?ytnoM
,god.ecioveht ta
Ó?dnim ruoy egnahc uoy edam tahWÒ
.tuoba gnippiz liat ,seye sih sllor eH Ó!emit eht lla
.slainnereP .esuoh eht fo esab tnorf eht dnuora srewolf tup ot gniog mÕI ,hguoht ,tsriF !yssalC .meht dnuora tliub reirrab kcirb a htiw ,esuoh eht fo edis tfel eht no sehsub emoSÒ
Ó.ereh ,htiw gnilaed
Ó.ecar txen ym rof ecitcarp ot ffo mÕI ,yawynAÒ
.sksa recnuonna na
.weiv morf gnikcud ylkciuq
eht gid ,ynnoL ,oYÒ Ó.ezis yb
.ssenelohw lautirips fo
Ó?gnidih uoy era tahWÒ
.tuoba gnivrews ylizal liat ,nirg a aremac eht gnivig ,syas eh Ó?thgir I mAÒ
.hcuoc ydnugrub ,ywollip a dnuora sklaw yeldirF
Ó.em thguac uoy ,thgirlAÒ
Ó É erofeb deneppah sÕti erus mÕI ,wonkÕy
?atosenniM morf mÕI enoyreve gnillet dnuora og I oD
fo gnileef a sevig yllaer roloc sihTÒ
.snruter recnuonna ehT         .EDOSIPE FO DNE
,orP relloR tleP detadpu eht htiw ,woNÒ
dna aremac eht ta skool anidE
Ó!ylliB ,taerg skooLÒ
Ó,laiceps era hteet ruoYÒ
Ó!mih no ffo bur llÕti ebyam É llew
Ó.oot ,rettam sliat sselruf esuaceB .xoS-TÒ
Ó?hOÒ Ó!nam ,swen doog
:riahc weivretnI .slap sih htiw tuo gnignah dna gnihgual ,tneve eht ta ekalB fo oediv erom si erehT Ó.taht
.ylsuovren sremmats eh Ó!gnihton-NÒ
Ó.nam ,ecim gni-)PEELB(Ò :ekalB Ð riahC weivretnI
.tohsrae fo tuo si ekalB erus sÕeh litnu neercs-ffo gnikool
,esuom eht ediseb pu seldis enilef ynwarb ,gib ehT Ó!eno dooGÒ
.nediw seye sÕlerriuqs ehT
.seohce anidE Ó?raguoc ehTÒ
:riahC weivretnI
.ediskcab sÕknumpihc ÕtneconniÔ eht revo
Ó.ffutS ruoY lerriuqS sÕtI
.emas eht si llaw yrevE .stnemevom sih swollof aremac ehT
.snoitcerid gnignahc ,stniop eH
sÕynnoL Ó.krad eht ni skrow tIÒ
yeldirF yspit-imes ,deticxe na sllup eh sa skrims ytnoM Ó?noos woHÒ
,tseretni evol laitnetop sÕanidE ,sgnilliB
.riahc weivretni eht no desucof sniamer tub kcab sesae aremac ehT
.tey ereh dnuora enoyna wonk tÕnod os
?tac ,sediseBÒ
Ó?won sesuoh gnihtemos-06 ,tahw ,ta erÕeWÒ
a aremac eht sevig
?thgir ,moor yreve
.knis nehctik eht evoba sthgil doolf erutainim ,elbammid llatsni ot kaerb a gnikat si
Ó.eno neerg a ni ykcat kool tÕnow
,yxes si der ,hOÒ .sdda ytnoM
.gnihsulb era hcihw
,pohs eeffoc eht ta mÕI ,lleW .dneirflrig a evah tÕndid I woh tuoba Õniklat erew eWÒ
,enil hsinif eht sessorc ti sA
?gniwolfrevo egaraG
Ó,evren dehcnip a evah uoy ebyaMÒ
.tinu gnivlehs latem a tsniaga gninael ,dias ytnoM Ó,yllautcAÒ
,03:9 ta ,yllanif ,dnAÒ
.won sraey ynam rof selat cirtnec-rettirc gnitirw neeb sah ohw
Ó,melborp a eb nac tIÒ
Ó!tirips eht sÕtahTÒ
.daeh eht no ytnoM stap esuom reed etihw-dna-nworb ,derae-gib eht ,erutinruf fo egrahc nI
Ó.gnorw syawla si remotsuc eht
rof pu veR .thgir sÕtahT
,flesmih esopmoc ot sesuap ytnoM
,skaeuqs esuom eht Ó,gniyssuG .edud
Ó,moorhtab eht no krow llÕew ,siht retfAÒ
edis eht ot ffo serats neht dna tsehc sÕekalB ta skool eH
.lennut tsal taht fo edis rehtie no ecnaraelc sehcni owt ebyaM
Ó.monev noiprocs guhc yllacitcarp eW
.liat ypor sÕetam sih rof sehcaer dna selims yeldirF Ó?hOÒ
Ó,tnereffid si sihTÒ
?tahw os ,orb a sÕeh fi dnAÒ
.ynnoL ot revo yaw sih sekam eh sa
.krow sih htiw dehsinif sah sgnilliB erehw ,nehctik ot tuC
rehto hcae od annog erÕyehT .revetahw
a siht si É siht sIÒ
Ó?ylliB ,eno siht tuoba kniht uoy od tahWÒ
.dezinagro-llew sloot ruoy evah ot tnatropmi sÕti leef I tub ,flesmih peekpu eht eldnah naht rehtar renedrag a erih tsuj ylbaborp lliw ekalBÒ
,seralced recnuonna eht Ó,thgin worromoTÒ
,aremac eht ot kcab kool dna hgual
,gnitnalp ,gniggid
eno siht piks esaelp
Ó.tnaw uoy lla garBÒ .hctiwt A
.emaf fo tnuoma erucsbo nA
.hctiwt sreksihw siH
.haey É os ,tresed eht morf mÕIÒ   .gnihclum
.edis ot edis gninael ydob dna gnitrotnoc ecaf ,neercs a no
Ó?naem I tahw wonkÕy
!ti tÕnseod ,seilf emiTÒ .syas yeldirF
!htuom ruoy no ysae tub hteet no drah sÕtaht alumrof kcits wehc eht
Ó!gnihtyna ssim ton dna
ton mÕIÒ Ó.ebyam ,yvrucS
Ó.moor gnimag eht ni gniog saw ti thguoht I tub É thguoht IÒ
Ó É ay eeS .eruS !yako ,mUÒ
Ó.roloc ruf ruoy ton sÕtahTÒ
.sksa sgnilliB Ó?ohWÒ
.mih dnuora mra na gnittup
.tseb skool tahw enimreted ot llaw eht ot sehctaws tniap gnipat ,syas anidE
Ó.sgnilkaew rof ton sÕti tub ,trops laer a sÕti ,haeYÒ
.htrof dna kcab gniyaws ,reh dniheb swap reh gnipsalc ,syas anidE
:esuoH ruoY esuoM ,03:8 tAÒ
Ó.won ,moordeb eht ni gniog sÕeulBÒ
srebmem maet esuoH ruoY esuoM evif ehT
hcus ksa syawla uoy ,ylliBÒ
.esuap rehtonA Ó.sdeen
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.egatoof fo tresni na gnitiawa
,der moordeb eht ekam em tel
:ynnoL Ð riahC weivretnI
Ó?od I nac tahw tuBÒ
.msinahcem esnefed a sa msacras sesu ytnoMÒ
Ó.meÔ rof esu gni-)PEELB( yna evah tÕnod I dna
,haey ,devom tsuj I !eno tog tÕnoDÒ
.gnirob eb tub pleh tÕnac eh esoppus IÒ
.daeh sih sekahs eH Ó?uoYÒ .sksa ytnoM
,smra sih sessorc ytnoM Ó.ebyaMÒ
.gnithgil evol tsuj IÒ
.krep ot gnitrats ,sksa esuom reppohssarg eht
,rellevart wollef ruoy
detropsnart yllacigam
.swap sÕlerriuqs eht otni
Ó?oga skeew wef a etoyoc taht rebmemer
.resolc ni sehsup aremac ehT
?desolc É si eno txen ehT
orP relloR tleP a gninnur si allihcnihc eht erehw ,cisum yxes dna gnithgil deudbus htiw moor a ot stuc aremac ehT
Ó,desirprus eb tÕndluow IÒ .stseggus anidE
.tuoba gnildoon liat ,sesserp ytnoM
:riahc weivretnI .ecaf no lwocs ,spih no swap
,saelp Õsrenwoemoh deirrah srewsna
.kcalb ot tuC .kool etavirp a
!esuoH ruoY esuoM ,pu tsriFÒ
.ecaf sÕanidE no sesucof aremac ehT
,yawrood eht hguorht gnikeep
.gniyl yltcaxe ton ,syas anidE Ó,gnileef a dah I É IÒ
Ó,gniht tnatropmi ehTÒ
)PEELB(Ò .seye nedlog sih sllor eH
.niaga hsulb ot gnitrats era srae ÕsgnilliB
,ralloc trihs sÕyeldirF gnibbarg ,serussa ytnoM
,hctiwt sreksihw sÕesuom reed ehT
eht tAÒ .sehtolc reh revo norpa na gniraew si ehS
.cigam rieht krow ot syad evif evah yehT
,elap a yletanretla sÕtIÒ
Ó.yvne htiw ecalp siht elgo lliw yb seog ohw enoyreve ,enod mÕI nehWÒ ,gnisimorp
,ekalB ot snrut aremac ehT Ó!keEÒ
.eciov sih srewol eH
!enod eb llÕew ,worromot
,gnimialcorp ,sniojer recnuonna ehT
Ó.noitaicossa srenwoemoh eht htiw elbuort ni teg dÕeW .gib emoceb dluow taht gnihtyna rO
.sredluohs sÕetam sih gnigassam
.eciov sih srewol eH
.esuom tsevrah a osla sÕeH .syas
!wohs eht no gnipom ynnoL evah tÕnac ,naem IÒ
.rocŽd sih pu stes ytnoM elihw segde eht morf epat sÕretniap eht gnivomer tsuj si anidE
evah IÒ .ecaf sih no
.yrrufos.lerriuqs ta
.setarobale anidE Ó,neerg
!gnihctaw rof sknahTÒ
ekalB sIÒ .yllufepoh sesuap eH Ó.looc peek attoGÒ
)PEELB( ,ekil ,saw I ,srotaroced roiretni fo ecirp eht ta dekool I nehw dnAÒ
,nirg yhtoot a sehsalf raguoc ehT
.deggurhs enilef ehT
Ó É melborp eno ylnOÒ .esuap A
.ytitnedi na gnitteg yrT ?yako ,ti teg eW
.kcalb ot tuC Ó!Õno wang ot
desucof-rozar seye ,ecar enord a ta etis-no ekalB swohs egatooF
Ó.sreweiv ffo evird llÕtI
.rood tnorf eht tuo semoc raguoc eht sa ekalB ot
!hOÒ  Ó?pu sgniht gniyssuGÒ
Ó.pu kooh ot nwonk neeb evah stac dna ecimÒ
.rehtegot gnilruc sliat dekcos-liat
gnihtemos rof gnikool eb ot sdneterp ytnoM
,daeherof sih ot wap a stup eH
.rellevart wollef ruoy
Ó?yppah uoY .snoitome evah IÒ .esuap A Ó.ebyaMÒ
keerGÔ em dlot uoYÒ
emosevif yesuom suolubaf ruO
?redraoh a gnimoceb uoy era ,9 tAÒ Ó!oot
.krow lacirtcele dna noitcurtsnoc htiw deksat si eh
Ó,os epoh sÕteLÒ Ó.seod yllausU
.don lufpleh a htiw syas ytnoM Ó,raed ,thgir sÕeHÒ
Ó,wonk uoy tel ot yeldirF dlot IÒ
dennalp IÒ Ó?moor yreve
Ó!doog erÕuoY .nam ,haNÒ
Ó!ytilanosrep dlob ruoy tneserper ot sroloc noen ro ni gnidnelb rof senot hself nI
,aremac eht otni skool ynnoL
.moor gnivil ot tuC
Ó!em naht elbisnopser erom erÕuoy ,yllaer ,oSÒ
,seod tI !ylliB ,uoy knahTÒ
Ó?skcits wehc dlo esoht morf no evom ot ydaeR
Ó!seod eh ebyaM .lleWÒ
Ó É srehto naht ruf erom evah su fo emoSÒ
Ó É wohs siht no od I gnitfil yvaeh eht lla htiw tahWÒ .srettum ytnoM
ni smooz aremac ehT
:ytnoM Ð riahC weivretnI
.segnellahc ynnoL
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.hcum ton sÕti ,tnemtrapa na morf gnimoc tub ,ereht ni ffuts ym tog I
:yeldirF Ð riahC weivretnI
.eniwtne sliat riehT
É nwot ni stnedor tsellihc eht era yehT .sarabypaC ehT
.ynnoL ot ,edistuo tuC
revo raep frawd-imes a ,haey ,tuB Õ.yat-
.stniuqs etam ehT
,noitapicitna htiw gnippird eciov
.detcepxe tÕndah eh roloc a htiw gnitniap si ehs gniees
.tlit-daeh A Ó.thgiarts sÕeH
.gnitniap reh ot gninruter ,seilper anidE
.gnihtemos htiw nwod gnimoc erÕuoy ebyaMÒ
É gnileef saw I dna ,sdoom eripsni sroloCÒ
.sthgil gniliec eht ta pu skool neht eH
.ssalg a gnisiar ,sreehc yeldirF
Ó,nehctik eht tcepsni og annog mÕIÒ
.moor eht evael ot gniraperp ,syas yeldirF
.esuoh ot kcaB ÓÑdna
.gnittes si nus eht ,edistuO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.hgual eniuneg tseb sih seod ynnoL
.daetsni Õ,eniP reveroFÔ
:hsalfsweNÒ .sesuap eH
.hctiwt sreksihw
!taht htiw pleh nac slerriuqs ruO
.kcab snael yllausac ynnoL :riahC weivretnI
,etam sih yb denoitseuq gnieb si knumpihc elam a ,gnittes dlohesuoh cireneg a nI
,smra sih sessorc ynnoL .srednow ytnoM
,gnitsisni ,swollaws neht ehS
Ó.cirbaf gnigamad tuohtiw
,elyts-dlehdnah ,sevom aremac eht Õ,tneserpÔ eht ni kcaB Ó.peekpu woL
Ó.sdradnats evah ot desu yteicoSÒ
.yllaretiL .xof a sÕehS ?sddo
,swap sih no trid htiw seenk sih no sseltrihs llits ,esuom reppohssarg ehT
Ó.egieb eb ot mraw oot elttil AÒ
Ó!desuom yllufsseccus
Ó É ytxis revo sÕti kniht I
.moor gnivil eht dnuora snap aremac ehT
deruces sriah esool esoht lla steg
aremac eht sevig tub
Ó É tuB .tsom eht roloc siht dekil eh ,haeY ?ylliBÒ
.taorht sih sraelc eH  Ó.ydal ykcul
.krowidnah sih gnirimda
Ó.ÕsgnidnatsrednusimÔ
.llaw eht nwod dna pu rellor tniap a gnihsup
moor ot moor morf klaw nac I
Ó.dehcattanu si eh É tub ,sbrab oN
Ó.pu parw syug uoy nehw ytrap gnimrawesuoh eht ot reh gnirb annoG
Ó.ffo deriap yllaitnesse era ruof rehto ehT ?yako ,toh sÕekalBÒ
.reggats elttil a gniod
.ytrap gnimrawesuoH
Ó.recar enord lanoisseforp a mÕI .ainrofilaC morf
.sredisnoc dna moor eht revo skool ,tniap fo egrahc ni esuom tsevrah maerc-dna-dlog etuc a
tuohtiw sroloc eht ees ot elba eb tÕndluow uoy ,ekil ,tub ,sknahTÒ
.srettum ytnoM Ó,hsiw uoYÒ Ó!ssa ym dettap tsuj eHÒ .sraews ynnoL
,esuoM .T dleiF yb
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
Ó.tiuq tÕnod srelwoHÒ
.odneunni eht gnissim ,shgual raguoc ehT
.hcaeb ynnus a no liat denrubnus a ot eola ylppa yeht sa secniw tar ycnaf A
.htnom a ti evig IÒ :ytnoM
?htem É fo tol a ekam osla yeht tÕnoDÒ
.snapdaed ytnoM Ó,yarooHÒ
.esruoc elcatsbo na hguorht enord sih ylf ot lortnoc etomer a gnisu sÕeH
.ekalB deredliweb a ot
Ð riahC weivretnI ÓÑtuB .ebyam ,haeYÒ
.stsisni recnuonna eht Ó!xoS-T deen uoYÒ
Ó?ytnoM ?kniht uoy tÕnod ,ereh ni reilednahc a esu dluoCÒ
.si meht fo eno ,lleWÒ
Ð riahC weivretnI Ó.mmhmMÒ
,ecruos retaw a ot esolc oot meht tnaw tÕnod uoY
!pu decurps eb yllaer dluoC
Ó?tserof cihtoG desruc a oTÒ
,emarf eht sretne ynnoL ,sevael yeldirF sA
,yawevird eht ni si esuom reppohssarg ehT
ÓesuoH ruoY esuoMÒ
.elgna tnereffid a ot stuc aremac ehT
Ó.ekalB stif notuf A
,srae sih no ni smooz aremac ehT
Ó.neve tÕnac tsuj IÒ
esuoM .T dleiF yb
eht ni É haey É ebyam ,ereht
.remmus rof elbahtaerb dna thgil rO .retniw rof detalusni yllamrehT
.erutinruf eht htiw gnilddif llits si yeldirF
neerg sihTÒ Ó?ti tÕnseod
ni sÕVT eht tuoba wonk uoy diDÒ
Ó,morf emoc I erehWÒ
Ó,sllaw eht fo roloc eht htiw dnelb ot sah rocŽd yMÒ
ÓesuoH ruoY esuoMÒ
Ó.ereht thgir og dluoc ti thguoht I ?gniog K4 ym sÕerehw ,hu ,oSÒ .pu sbmuht elbuod a gnivig ,syas tac gniogysae ,ynwat eht Ó,eciiiNÒ
.edisni skool ,rood nepo na ta spots tI
gniredisnoc neeb dah I eulb fo edahs eht Õ,neriS keerGÔ dehctid I ,tnemom tsal
:ynnoL Ð riahC weivretnI
yojne esaelP  .moc.yrrufos.lerriuqs
.sesruoc tnereffid eerht no sdrocer dlrow evah IÒ
.doog neeb sÕyenom ezirP
Ó?tresed eht ni tuO
,ekiLÒ .serussa ytnoM
,wodniw eht ta skool enilef ehT
Ó.em denraw uoY .wonk I ,haeYÒ
,nehctik eht tub erehwyreve sÕK4 sÕekalB detnuom gnivah
Ó.xelpmoc rehtar yllautca si egieBÒ
É yltcaxe tÕnsi ekalB ecnis tnatropmi erom nevE
.yendoR demaN .lerriuqs epoletna na sÕeHÒ
.kcalb ot tuC Ó.detpeccA
:riahc weivretnI Ó.ti eparcs neve tÕndiD
!uoy dluohs rehtien dna ,gnihtyna rof pots tÕnod yehTÒ
Ó?enola owt uoy evael ,hu ,I dluohSÒ
.ti dniheb draeh eb nac sdnuoS .dekcoL
Ó,roloc relooc a htiw kcits ot deerga htob I dna ytnoM tub
Ó,ekalB ,lla ti evah uoy ekil mees uoYÒ   .edistuo ot tuC
.nediw seye sÕynnoL
:anidE Ð riahC weivretnI
.rekcor taob gni-)PEELB( a mÕI ?tahw
.stsisni anidE Ó,kcis
raeh tÕnseod yeldirF wonk uoYÒ
!flesruoy ot ruf ruoy peek nac uoy
Ó,desufnoc mÕI naem tÕnseod ib mÕI esuac tsuJÒ
sevlesmeht llac ot ekil ecim reppohssarGÒ :ytnoM
Ó,ynnoL ,radyag dab a hcus evah uoYÒ .srucco enoN
KAERB FO DNE     Ó!niw IÒ ,gnimialcorp dna revo sdrac rieht gnippilf
.nehctik eht no sehcuot gnihsinif eht gnittup sÕylliBÒ .syas anidE