”.seiceps ruoy ot dna slaudividni ot htob
tsuj tel t’nac I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?tuoba gniklat uoy era
.derots era taht seulav fo stros eht era esoht
,nosrednA esahC yb
swap sih no areneg eht ffo gnitnuoc nageb eH ”?gninaeM…“
”—raey eht yltnerruc s’tI .snoitseuq evah uoy erus m’I“
.emit siht hgis rieht ni ngier ot elba saw nefubeT
.thgiew rieht rednu gniknis
,noitcelloc laiceps rebotco ruo fo
,yhw enigami ot drah saw tI
.senalpria ,stekram kcots ,setilletaS
.slammam morf serats htiw laed ot gnivah tuohtiw
”.taorht ruoy s’tahT“
.sesabatad ruoy morF“ ”?atad-D“
.retsasid deksir ti
ot derehtob reven ,koot siht gnol woh demit reven dah yehT
maerd gnol lanif eht erofeb thgir
”.enildaed tcirts a hcus s’ereht ecniS“ .dedda yeht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.decrovid tog enoemos etad tahw ro ohw deris ohw rebmemer ot elba eb reven ll’I ,egral os eb lliw tesatad eht ,sediseB
moor eht ni saw ohw dezilaer yeht litnu ,yas dluow srekrow-oc rieht fo emos sa ”,gub“ A .ekulf a s’ti
.ezorf eh dna tem seye riehT
.3202
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.…uoy era tahw ,riS“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .goD fo tsohG
gnikrow edoc s’erutan
D“ .yraropmet ylno saw ti tub ,rehtie ,yhsiuqs dna etihw gnieb ekil t’ndid yehT
.kcart ot tol a saw ereht dna ,srotsecna dna seirotsih ylimaf gnikcart tuoba lla erew stibbaR .esnes ekam dluow taht ,thgiR
rof eludehcs margorP gnidaeR remmuS ruo fo dne eht si sihT
”?ynnuf taht dnif uoy oD“
.dnim s’nefubeT ni gnizillatsyrc nageb seussi laitnetop ehT
.rojam gnihtemos fo psuc eht saw ti tuB
”?sraey 21 tsal eht revo tser eht lla ot neppah gnihtemos diD“
gnikrow deppots yeht fi smelborp laer esuac dluoc taht erutcurtsarfni lacitirc htiw lla ,snoitazinagro elpitlum erew erehT
”?…eb dluow taht dnA“
.detcejretni dralluN .rM
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.gnorw erew srebmun eht wenk yeht ,etats dezad rieht ni nevE .gnorw saw
dnatsrednu I dna ,ti xif ot m’I fi ot evah I ,dralluN .rM“
”.serutcurts lanretxe lla dehs eW“
tahW…“ .derats tibbar ehT
.ecaparac dlo eht otni gninil laehcart eht deppord yehT
”?ti ekat I ,ssenisub etavirP“
.neppah ylneddus dluow siht
.gnirob osla s’ti tub ,siht ekil m’I nehw evael t’nac I
!noitamrofni yrateirporp s’taht-t-
.rehto yna morf tnereffid on esiwrehto tub
.gninekawa otni hguorhtkaerb neddus eht fo
”.nefubeT .xM ,tnemtraped erutlucirga eht htiw ma I“
,ytinummoc nwo rieht dah tsael ta yeht tuB
.tciderp ot drah dna suoiretsym erew sretupmoc fo erutuf eht tuoba sgniht ynaM
.ylevissimsid dnah rieht devaw tibbar ehT
gnihtemos wenk yletaidemmi yehT
”.gub siht etacidare ot detiurcer neeb sah elbaliava remmargorp yrevE
.dehsiws liat s’drehpehs ehT
.gnimoc saw wenk lla yeht eussi siht sserdda ot sraey detiaw lla dah yeht ekil tsuj
.rehto eht naht dehctip rehgih eno
saw tI .duol ,thgirb
”!won remmargorp DLOBOK a deen I
”?stlom neewteb worg ew kniht uoy od esle woH“ .dias nefubeT
.yleritne taht diova ot dediced nefubeT os ,sa meht ot derrefer uoy seiceps tahw tuoba ralucitrap yrev erew yehT
,etihw saw gnihtyrevE
,ega dezilivic siht ni enog gnol saw
”.taht nialpxe ot eno eht eb dluow dralluN .rM“ ”?em
!syad evah t’nod eW“
tuo gnitros no detsaw erew sthguoht gnimmid rieht daetsnI
.krow tnemnrevog rof yhsalf dna enif oot saw tius esohw
”.ssecorp ysae na ton s’tI“
”—eb ot evah lliw sraey ehT
”.slammam uoy rof nevE“ .denialpxe yeht
”.nedrah secaparac ruo litnu emoh evael t’nod eW
”,rekam yenom laer eht tegrof t’nod dnA“
,seigolaeneg s’ti ,atad ehT“
dnim rieht fo tuo taht fo lla dehsup nefubeT .meht fo eno ton saw sraey eht fo noissergorp evitareti ehT
,rebmun emirp rehtona ,raey doog a saw ti
ekaw ot dah uoy taht tnatropmi os s’taht kaerb ot gniog s’tahw ,oS“
knarhs ecaps elbaliava ehT
”?eil sgod gnipeels tel t’nac uoy dnA“ .hgis rehtonA
,dengila yltcefrep erew srebmun eht nehw retteb dekrow gnihtyrevE
”,paehc emoc t’nod secivres yM“
,meht troppus ot metsys a saw erehT
”K2Y OT X EVOM“   yojne esaelP
.gninedrah llits erew sesnel wen rieht sa yrrulb llits saw thgis rieht tub ,egdab eman rieht fo daer a teg ot deirt yehT
.evitcelfer-fles tsael ta ro ,dercas
.drehpehs eht ot denrut nefubeT ”.…rednairoc ,nimuc ,yelsrap ,lennef ,llid ,yawaraC“
,yranidroartxe t’nsaw flesti ni tahT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.elbissop sa tneiciffe sa eb ot gniyrt m’I os ,trohs si emit
”?secips rof pu em ekow uoY“
.ylesuforp ezigolopa dna
.mih derongi nefubeT tub ,gnihtemos
,21 neeb ylno dah ti tub ,dessap dah rebmun emirp a retfa nekawa ot ylno erew yehT
.lla ta esac eht ton s’taht
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.derehtob reven yeht os ,syawyna ,ekowa yeht emit yreve degnahc lla tI
,taht tpurretni dluow emit rehto yna ta ekawa gnieB
.etisbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,wollahs saw gnihtaerb riehT
,tliub erusserp ehT
”.revo ti kool ll’I dna worromot noitatnemucod edoc revetahw dna atad elpmas emos em gnirB
,eninac a saw ehS
,retirw noitcif evitaluceps a
”!srefillebmu s’ti ,seigolaeneg ylimaf t’nsi sihT
.eerf tel eb ot gnihca elahxe eht ni dleh yeht sa demsaps sedis riehT ”!storraC“
trapa ecaparac dlo eht daerps nefubeT ”.wonk I ,sey ,seY“
.rebmahc eht hguorht deohce dnuos gnippir tnasaelpnu eht sa revo deleek tibbar ehT
.htiw emit dneps ot seno devol dna sdneirf
.raey wen eht no gnihsarc fo ksir eht snur setad sesu taht gnihtynA“
tuoba no derebbaj eH
.dehgis yehT ”.erutlucirgA“
,tibbar eht ot dekool yehT
”.erehpsimeh siht ni erawtfos lacigolaeneg tsenif eht fo emos fo OEC dna rednuof ,esruoc fO“
.rekihhctih flowerew
dna snimda esabatad ,sreenigne metsys ,nefubeT ekil sremmargorp rehto erew erehT .tuo thguoht oot
.eerf gnikaerb no desucof yeht sa
.teef sih ot delffuhs tibbar ehT
.dellews ydob rieht sa
T“ ”.ti rof ssecorp a ngised dna tamrof wen a ot detadpu eb tsum sdleif tahw tuo erugif ot deen I
,sevlesmeht dlot yeht
.tuo dekaeuqs tibbar eht ”?syad-
,cinap t’noD .detcepxe sa
,semirp owt neewteb deltsen yltcefrep
,drib tenretni dna
.yaw siht kool I yhw si hcihw ,dne ot ssecorp siht rof syad lareves sekat tI“
ydaerla hguone ysub saw raey gnikaw rieht os
.dehsiw yeht fi neve siht hsur t’ndluoc yehT
,sraey fo snoillim retfa
!KCARC neht ,niap eht
,israt rieht dexelf yehT
.dehgis nefubeT ,niaga ecnO
.deniamer ssenilredro rof erised deniargni eht tub
oog dna elcituc dna ria fo sreyal
”K2Y OT X EVOM“ saw sihT     ”.ylurt ,emahs A“
.tsaf t’nsaw ti tub ,pu ti kool
,meht rof yltnereffid nar emiT .esruoc fo ,tibbar A
.peels gnol rieht gnirud ylefas desuoh erew yeht erusne ot
,tluciffid eb dluow eludehcs-ffo taht htiw gnilaeD
.dlrow eht fo dne eht naem dluoc taht ycnegreme na saw gnihtyreve
”!ti ta kool enoyna
.srae ytniop ,tcere htiw drehpehs fo tros emos
,ydaetsnu erew sgel dnih riehT .tuo pets ot
,elggiw tsellams eht rof hguone tsuj
,won ecaps saw erehT
eht dengis dna diputs yllaer saw enoemos fi ,99- rO .0 raey eb noos dluow tI
.ti otni desserp ecaparac dlo eht sa nwod gnihsiuqs ti fo ,gnitrecnocsid saw hself tnailp ,tfos fo gnileef ehT
,nosrednA esahC yb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
lavivrus erusne ot
,meht ees ot yppah t’nerew ynaM
,tiaw dluoc ti tuB
.ssecorp ,gnirraj fi ,railimaf a saw sraey eht fo gninrut ehT  nosrednA esahC yb
srebmun eht ot erehda ot evitarepmi ehT .gninekawa ot
.drehpehs eht fo thgieh eht flah ylisae saw eH
reraelc emaceb seciov ehT
”.netfo sdoporhtra htiw krow t’nseod tnemtraped yM .seigolopa yM“
,hceeps eb dluoc taht sesion delffuM
.gnidnapxe yldipar dna etihw
.noitautis eht ta noitartsurf rieht gnigdelwonkca deppetsedis osla ti tub ,eurt saw tI
.saw eussi eht tahw ezilaer ot tnemom a koot tI .yhctarcs
”,surot a si ydob ehT“
”?enosydce fo esu lagel a neve siht sI“
.gniyonna erom dna
.llehs dlo eht tsniaga desserp bmil a
.pu meht ekow ohw
”,eef hsur a eb ll’ereht dnA“
dnuora dehsif dna strap htuom rieht tsap deppid nefubeT .htiw revo siht teg retteB
,rebmuls peed otni tnecsed eht saw erehT
,ylrae X doorb gninekawa yllaitrap fo snoissucreper eht dnatsrednu eW“
,on on on on on on hO“
,ssensuoicsnoc fo tuo dna ni gnimaerd denrettap eht fo
.war eciov ,dias yeht ”,seY“
,relgnarw teehsdaerps
.t’ndid yllaer ehS
edosipe tsrif eht uoy gnignirb eb ll’ew ,emit txeN
”,eussi eht fo epocs eht dnatsrednu uoy kniht t’nod I“
,lamrof oot saw siht tuB
”K2Y OT X EVOM“
.eson reh gnirevoc ,dehguoc neht dna deffins ehS
”.nefubeT .xM“ .detcerroc yeht ”,nefubeT“
.sraey 71 eht revo
.tsehc sih tuo deffup dralluN .rM
.yas ot dediced yeht
:laed eht s’ereH“
,wols eb ot desoppus saw ssecorp ehT
.naorg a saw noitalahxe tsrif riehT ”!ecnirP eht yB“
”.yad eno neve rof nwod gniog erawtfos ruo fo egamad dnarb laitnetop eht naht repaehc hcum eb ll’ti ,tsoc eht revetahW“
.pirg doog a teg dluoc yeht litnu
.9991 si raey ehT .thgir ,hA
.slamina tsom rof gnihton tnaem tI
.detnarg rof koot tsom serutcurts eht otni s0 dna s1 gnilgnarw fo syaw dlo eht derebmemer ohw stsilaiceps TI
.dias drehpehs eht
”.nefybbeT .rM ,secnatsmucric yranidroartxe htiw gnilaed er’eW“
,delffum dna depraw erew sdnuoS .regetni
.muinnellim wen eht fo htrib eht ta
.elbissopmi eb dluow taht dna
,sevaw eht gniyaced dna gnibrosba
,dias god eht ”,…sseldrageR“ .dezilaer yeht
.lufyoj eb ot desoppus saw ti ,gnissapmocne lla
”.dednemmocer ylhgih emac uoy
,raey a rof uoy tcartnoc ylno nac I taht emahs a tsuj s’tI .sey ,seY“
.swalc lasrat rieht dnuora dnuow ebut yhself eht ta decnalg adacic ehT ”?yrassecen yllaer taht saW“ .lworg A
”,dnapxe ot shtaerb peed deen I“
koot ydob rieht smhtyhr larutan eht wonk ot hguone gnol evila neeb dah nefubeT
.roolf eht no seohs fo sdnuos tcnitsid eht erew ereht tub
yawrednu-llew saw sisydce ;ehtaerb ot elba erew yeht fi dehgis evah dluow nefubeT