fo sniur eht ta gnittiS  kcezzoW rreH yb meop a ,”sretaW ykruM“   yojne esaelP  remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
,niatnuof wen siht morf hsur sevaw gnitaludnU
,stahw dna syhw dna sohw fo elip sseldnE
derettacs ecno smaerd fo htineZ a
.eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL dna
,eireganeM oirT htiw mrofrep meht ees osla nac uoY
,ecafrus eht sdrawot uoy hsup yeht sa dna
esuaP ot sah eno
.nozamA no stamrof koobe dna kcabrepap ni tuo yltnerruc
semoc ereht ,neht tuB
,ni doolf yllanif efilretfA
noitcelloc yrteop desaeler-yltnecer rieht morf si meop sihT .notsoB ni desab
.ydduM  nur evah niatnuof eht morf tfel sretaw ruoy taht slievnu thgiL eht
:hserf dna lufitnelp dna
ni scitilop moorkcab fo ehcnalava eht ni sevlesruo gnilliK tsrif tuohtiw
fo esimorp eht htiw
tooB dna pihW slevon eht fo rohtua eht osla era yehT
dna sretcarahc dna seirots fo thguoht ew woh fo tcepsa yrevE
,skcirb rieht rehtag dna
,ew hcihw morf eloh eht ni sU
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sretteL amginE ehT
wolfrevO niatnuof eht seod suht
fo tuo eno sllup tahT
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
eht hguorht gnitfis
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
,skcirb weN htiw semoc ohw enO
tpek skcirb eht woh fo thgis gnisoL
,ytivitaerc fo niatnuof eht
.tnuocca ytiniffAruF rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,kcezzoW rreH yb ”sretaW ykruM“ saw sihT   sretaw ykruM
epacse ot depoh evah dluoc reveN
retirw dna ,tsinimerehT ,tsiloiv ,resopmoc a si ohw
,llew wen a dliub ot
.retaw-efil evititepmoc ruo detaerc taht slloR
luftiurf niameR reverof lliw hcihw
,kcezzoW rreH yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
esimorp taht ,noitaerC
,relevart wollef ruoy floWcaM boR si sihT
,noititepmoc fo thgiew eht ni dehcnerd
dnah dehctertstuo ehT  .hsiugna morf
siht fo sretaw eht taht
,selat fo esimorp eht htiw
ecidujerp emertxe hguorht ylno si ti ,semitemoS
:seitilibissop htiw su gniraD eno