”.evah ydaerla uoy tahw
.retal syad ytriht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof
,oga sraey ytnewT  xofhcaeB yb
dluow saw ti sa cilbup naciremA eht woh ees t’ndluoc tsuj I
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,xofhcaeB yb
— .MP3 tsomla s'tI
.kniht uoy naht retsaf tfihs nac yteicoS
.senil eht tsap og ot sruoted ekam sessub ruot ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.dneirf s’elpuoc yag eht syas
,sklawedis eht tih eW
.adnutoR llaH ytiC ocsicnarF naS eht nees ev’uoy
,god.ecioveht ta
nlocniL fo eutats a yb ssap eW
.eciffo sdrocer egairram eht ot ti ekam eW
.deirram llits dna
,tniop taht ta deirram ydaerla erew ew tub
dworc eht ot krowrepap rieht gnivaw ,llaH ytiC fo tuo gnimoc saw elpuoc wen a ,etunim rehto yrevE
,lagel-ton repus si tihs siht lla dnA
.tniop no dna derettilg-eb dna deffulf si draeb reh dna no puekam reh lla htiw puteg nun reh ni pu enod s’ehS
noitom eht gniweiver eb lliw dna
.ytiruces revoc ot slortap od ot emit diapnu reetnulov ot gnilliw erew spoc FS hguone ,tuo snruT
.redneg emas eht fo srehto ot meht fo emoS
.tnetxe na hcus ot ytinamuh ni stsixe taht ssendoog eht tlef erofeb reven dah I dna yoj dna
,siht od ot yad tsal eht si yadnoM
.enod tsuj d’ew tahw fo ssenlaerrus eht ni tfirda
.yllareneg su rof dereehc d’ohw
uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
!taocniar tfihsekam a tog ev’uoy dna smra dna daeh eht rof seloh tuC .enoyreve rof sgab egabrag htiw pu swohs enoemos nehw 7 dnuora s’tI .lwarc
,elknirps thgil a tsuj
.sraey thgie rof rehtegot neeb ev’yehT
.retfa nepo ti gnikcarc tuoba yrrow ot evah ton dna
.ocsicnarF naS ni dnekeew dliw tsrif taht fo gnitnuocer etarucca %001 a ton si sihT
.yadot retal sraey ytnewt s’ti dnA
ecnahc tsal eht ,egairram
.won oot deirram ylbaborp era mih ees dluow
.yas ew ”!esruoc fO“
royaM nwod tuhs yllanif dna tfel gnihton evah yeht erofeb
.lla retfa ,lagelli saw tihs tahT
htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.knilb sa hcum os dluow devlovni eno on yletulosba dna
sgniddew ocsicnarF naS eht nwod tuhs ot
.sraet yppah gniyrc dna daeherof ot daeherof rehto hcae gnigguh
21 yraurbeF morf ecalp koot
eciton trohs no teg dluoc yeht tihs tsecin eht ni tuo dekced snaibsel dna syag fo sderdnuh tog ev’uoy oS
nepo seciffo gnisnecil egairram eht evah ot
.ti rebmemer I sa rebmemer I gnihtyreve tuo etirw ot
nwod su gnittuhs eb yllatot ll’yeht os
s’dnabsuh ym no gnir eht teg t’nac I dna ,gnirebbulb ma I
pu esor dnuorg eht ekil saw ti dnA .repap fo eceip siht tog ew neht tuB
,dias eH ”.mosweN s’tahT“
.tciderp t’nac uoy syaw ni
.sraey owt naht sseL
,os ro xis ylno s’ti os
ni ton si mosweN royaM
.ti rof elbuort em evig ot tnaw yeht fi erac t’nod I“
sgniddeW tsetorP xeS-emaS eht sa nwonk osla ,ytinutroppO fo sgniddeW ocsicnarF naS ehT
txen eht woh si ereH
.em rof liated a rebmemer ot
.enod segairram rieht teg ot yadnuS
dekram kcalb htiw spam llaH ytiC dna slamina deffuts dna seton pu dedlof dna srewolf dna srettel fo edacirrab etulosba eht fo esuaceb
.nac yeht sa tsaf sa hguorht elpoep gnissecorp tsuj era dna
,ot sdeen eh strap eht ffo sdnes
tnemesab eht otni nwod
gnipael dna gnireehc dna
fo tuo gniklaw erew ew tnemom emas eht tuoba OFS
,elobrepyh tuohtiw ,yas nac I .elbidercni
.sraey evif nihtiw deirram gnitteg eb ot detcepxe reven I
.rekihhctih flowerew
,yad txen eht pu ekaw eW
.snav swen yna neve ylerab
— .htrof os dnA .edishtuoS no dereviled era sesoR
?ereh eb ot su rof thgir ti sI
,su ta nworht ecir s’ereht
ffats eht gnippirtstuo raf saw
srood eht hguorht tsrif eb ot pu er’ohw
.dlrow eht ni tneced dna doog gnihtyreve gniyortsed morf
.tsaE ecaf srood ehT
dnabsuh won ym fo erutcip a ekat I
.ibbaR dna seilimaf rieht htiw syob hsiweJ fo riap A
,ma 03:6 s’tI
.ti tsniaga pu delip
— .og ot yaw -gnol- a evah llits eW
,yadot etov eht tuo evird ot snoitisoporp dna sllib snart-itna dna airetsyh snart-itna pu gnippihw era sevitavresnoc ekil hcum dna
rebmemer syawla dnA
.sthgir livic rof dna noitagerges tsniaga sngis dna srennab gnidloh
.sreehc eht ni denioj I nehT
.emit tsrif eht rof deirram tog I
”yadiloh a s’tI“ .deksa I
.ffo ti kconk meht ekam dna ni emoc ot
.adnutoR eht ot enil eht nioj dna krowrepap ruo ekat eW
.lliw s’doG tsniaga si siht woh tuoba ngis llams a htiw mih secalper nun A
sraey ytnewt neeb s’tI
…s’tI  .hguoht ,yad eht fo tsom tuo gnignah pu dniw eW .yadrutaS
.ni evil ew eno eht eb ot evah t’nseod
.yoj lanoitidnocnu reh ta
.dlrow siht ni evil d’I thguoht reven I
.no retal nwo sih no deweivretni teg ot
,mrots a fo elddim eht ni llits
eussi-non a hcus eb d’ti dna
.teef ruo teem ot
.laer dna dilos erom sgniht edam tI .retteb saw tI
.yadnoM ,yad txen eht kcab emoc ro ,pu denepo taht ecaps a saw ereht fi ees ot tiaw rehtie dluoc ew
tis fo tros tsuj dna pu lruc dna steknalb ni sevlesruo yrub eW
.yrruh a nI .dehsuR
elpuoc naibsel a era su dniheB
,yraurbeF s’tI .llaf ot gnitrats si ksud oS
.su rof yppah os tsuj er’yeht esuaceb enil ni elpoep ot sguh evig ot tnaw tsuj ohw
,loohcshgih ni saw I nehW
ylneddus tfihs nac erutluc ,naht rehtO
.yad eht rof esolc yeht erofeb srood eht hguorht teg ot elba eb tnow ew taht citnarf/deracs/suovren os si enoyrevE  .yppah os si
.deirram er'ew nehT
.krowrepap eht tuo gnidnah gnola semoc enoemos taht
.niaga egairram lagel a did ew ,8002 ni dnA .neht erofeb )erofeb sruoh
— .niar rof desserd ton dah eW
,eciffo eht tih uoy litnu os ro ruoh na s’tI“
.gniod era seiddub enil ruo woh rednow I
thgiew yna dloh neve t’ndid ti ,yllageL
.MA03:6 ta llaH ytiC ta evirra eW
sehcterts enil ehT
?thginrevo tuo gnah elpoep evah ot elba eb ot gniog t’nerew yeht yhw rebmemeR  .oS
.deirram teg lliw
.tcaf eht retfa sraey ytnewt
sgabhsart gniraew
.su naht redlo owt ro edaced a elpuoc yag a era su fo daehA
”retaL sraeY ytnewT
”?su ot ti liam tsuj uoy t’naC“
.su ot kcab tser eht sdnah dna
.gninnirg morf dehca yllaretil
noititep eht detcejer sah
?uoy htiw er’ew yas ew naC“
pu wohs ot semit htiw stekcit nevig neeb dah
”.ot dewolla eb ot gniog ton er’ew ,nwod su tuhs struoc eht tnemom eht tub ,haey ,yllamroN“
.elbissop ti ekam ot rehtegot emac ohw
)lleh gni'f eht woh ,sraey ytnewt fo(
”,looc hO“  ”.worromot
.no er’ew llaH ytiC fo edis hcihw no desab ti erusaem I .sessap emiT
mrofrep ot elba saw ytic eht taht detamitse si tI
,yrots eurt a si gniwollof ehT
.ytiruces dna meht rof seitilicaf era ereht sselnu siht ekil thginrevo tuo gnah elpoep evah ot dewolla ton er’eW“
”?-siht- si kcuf eht tahW“ .og eW ”.hU“
.deneppah yllaer hcihw
”.meht kcuF .ti htrow si sihT
,s09 etal eht ni
emit rieht reetnulov ot tnaw ohw
,won ,ogeiD naS ni nwod evil eW
,gnihtemos ro ,erutluc deniargni ro ,thgiew
dna dnuora sekans nehT .seirots rehgih eht hguorht seog enil eht ,emit sihT
,tnuts lacitilop a s’ti
,niar eht fo tuo elpoep teg ot yllaitraP
”.ereht thgir elpuoc a htiw t’nsi ohw ni enoyna
"!ti tuoba pu tuhS .erehwyreve lagel s'tI
,tol elohw eht dna slortap ecilop dna elpoep dnasuoht a rof seittoP-atroP deen d’eW
.rlbmuT no xofhcaeBlaeRehT dna
htiw ynomerec etavirp a enod d’eW
.ediS htroN eht no er’ew nehw dereviled era sgabhsart dna eeffoC
,skcab tsniaga ,sllaw tsniaga krowrepap eht tuo gnillif emit ruo dneps eW
,sevlesruo enifed ot si ti sa yrassecen sa
yaw ruo pmil ot nigeb ew dna
gnitiaw ton rof retal meht ot dezigolopa I .llaH ytiC
.segairram s’mosweN
niart TRAB tsrif eht hctac neht dna ,peels ,emoh teg ot si teb tseb ruoY
”!gnol dnekeew lla meht gniod er’yehT
,ti spmats ,ti sweiver ,krowrepap ruo sekat eH .yenom ruo
derehtag era sessentiw dna slaiciffo egairram erehw aera nepo eht koolrevo taht seinoclab eht gnola pu tes stops nezod a yllaretil era erehT
,syas rentrap reh ”,yhw meht dlot I“
emit eht ekat tub
enilno tra citoreomoh gnitsop neeb s’ohw xofhcaeB yb
evah ot tcepxe ew
,ecnartne tnorf eht ot daeh ew ,tuo teg eW
edisni ydaerla era selcnu siH
.elbissop sa sroodni elpoep ynam sa teg ot yltsom
.knoh snroh rac elihw KCUL DOOG tuohs dna saremac
,syas eno rehto eht ”,-siht- decnuonna yeht nehT“
deirrow saw yddub-enil eno eht stnerap esohw sdik ehT
.rulb diculimes a ni sessap htuos pirt eht dna sevirra niart ruO
,spets eht ta derehtag su fo derdnuh lareves eht morf gnireehc artxe fo evaw neddus a saw ereht
otni gniylf erew yehT
”.siht od ot teg dluoc uoy dalg
metsys lagel ainrofilaC eht rof koot ti sa gnol sa rof tsal ot gniog ylno saw ti tuB
.eciffo egairram eht otni seog enil ehT
”.dessorc sregnif ruoy peek dna ma5 ta pu
.esnecil ruo teg ot
enoyrevE  .ti revo
.ti htiw yako eb reve
,ega nwo sih tuoba lrig deriah dnolb a yb desahc ,emit siht dnuora
ediwnoitan lagel eb ot ti detcepxe reven I
etats cibohpomoh s’hsuB tnediserP ot esnopser ni ,selpuoc xes-emas ot sesnecil egairram eussi ot krelc ytnuoc eht detcerid emosweN nivaG royam-neht nehw ,4002 ,11 hcraM ot
sgalf "!sthgiR namuH era sthgiR yaG" dna ’!llA rof egairraM‘ htiw
enil ni teg ew nehT
.rehcaet loohcs a si eno redlo ehT
,gniniar regnol on s’tI
tnua ym fo tol lufwa na em sdnimer ohw namow etihw A
)em yb( dias era sdrow edins fo tol A  .od yeht seY
.ocsicnarF naS fo royam detcele ylwen eht saw eh ,emit eht tA
,lliK a ot weiV A :dnoB semaJ nees ev’uoy fI
noitapicitna htiw gnitarbiv dna detsuahxe dna
).seod eh tahw s'taht esuaceb derebmemer evah ll'eh tub
,flesym deirram gnitteg yadretsey ereh saw I ,hO“
niaga lagelli lla meht ekam dluow hcihw no detov eb ot 31 noitisoporP saw ereht esuaceB
gnikcuf uoy t’noD“  .erom
ytic eht ot rood txen gnivil etipseD
lateicos tsuj s’ti ebyam tuB
wols a ta drawrof peerc lliw ti ,ma7 ta nepo srood eht ecnO
oga sraey ytnewt fo elbanigaminu ehT
.sesor teg eW .azzip teg eW
.uoy llet I ,taert a si erutcip ehT .regnif
.rehtegotla seussi egdew rehto otno
”.yadsendeW litnu kcis
.mrots a fo elddim eht ni naeco eht fo elddim eht ni rehto hcae otno gnidloh htob erew ew ekil s’tI“
s04 ym ni eb d’I thguoht reven I
rehtegot llits er’ew dna
.su sllet sreetnulov eht fo enO ”.elbissop eb ot gniog ton s’taht diarfa m’I ,haeY“  .ksa ew ”?-won-
.tnorf yreve no kcab devohs gnitteg erew sthgir yag ,4002 saw ti( sraey erom 51 tsael ta rof
reganeet gnikool detsuahxe na yb desurep htob
,did ew emit emas eht dnuora detrats d’yehT
.ti sdeen reveohw rof llaH ytiC ot dereviled dna klub ni deredro era slegab dna eeffoC
.ffuts yag-itna lla saw ti 4002 ni
,htuos kcab niart ruo rof gnitiaw er’ew ,noitats TRAB eht ta m’I
.noitats TRAB eht ot kcab
— ”!eno txen eht rof ereht eb tsuj ll’I
lufetarg reverof ma I
.meht ssecorp ot dnah no dah yeht
nemow tneicna owt fo otohp egap tnorf eht rebmemer llits I
.yad taht ot pu saw hsuB W egroeG tnediserP tihsllub
elpoep eht rof s’tahT
,siht gniod fo tuo elpoep klat ot seirt
saw emit eht ta yhposolihp yM
.srobhgieN eniL evah eW
,gnihtyna naem yllaer t’now ti
.won yb egelloc detaudarg evah lliw
.no gniog saw tahw draeh yeht ecno dnekeew eht rof nwod evord yehT
.ti sekahs dna sih fo htob htiw ti spsalc
.tnuts lacitilop a saw tI
,yrots eurt a ni rewop a si ereht
,si laed gib eht lla tahw tuoba desufnoc yrev os si dik ehT
.ocsicnarF naS morf gninruter era ohw srehto tuo kcip dna tsap gniklaw elpoep hctaw dna wodniw eht yb tis eW
noitcelloc s’dnabsuh eht fo tuo debbarg seno tsuj ton( sgnir reporp
serutcip ekat I  .tsap sraey fo snoitartsnomeD llaH ytiC fo sotohp dna syalpsid htiw dellif ,saera cilbup eht fo eno retne eW
sdnasuoht eht yb pu wohs lliw
,noonretfa-dim eht ni tniop emos tA
sdrocer egairram eht fo esac a fo tnorf ni gnidnats
.retfa tnereffid saw ti tub
.tuo gnimoc saw eno on hguoht neve
.rehtona fo smra eht ni eno ,tuo emac stiftuo dnab ihcairaM lluf
.deirram teg ew litnu
.noitnevnoc a ta emit eht ta etats fo tuo neeb dah stnerap yM
,sraey dna sraey rof rehtegot neeb s’taht elpuoc yag dlo eht eb ot gniog -er’uoy- yademoS .ot -evah- uoy“
.emit taerg a gnivah s’eh os ,gniknoh dna yb gnivird peek sessub eht dna azzip eerf s’ereht tub
.noitats TRAB tsom-nrehtuos eht ot htron evird eW .ylrae pu teg ew
.skoob no ,sroolf enots no
,dekahs sdnah teg ew
.niar eht fo tuo dna srood eht hguorht ti ekam yllanif ew nehw
esoht fo enon taht niar ni
tuhs srood eht nehw
,adnutoR eht ot og ,thgirlA“
ti etagen t’ndluoc yeht dna
4002 yaD senitnelaV litnu nam eht fo draeh neve t’ndah I ,efil ym lla
htnom lluf a ylraen rof tuo ssecorp eht gard ot skcirt citarcuaerub ralimis yalp ot deecorp dluow truoC emerpuS etatS ehT
em fo efil eht rof rebmemer tonnac I laiciffo detcele rehto emos si tnaiciffo egairram ruO
emitefil a ni ecno laretil
,raey noitcele na saw 4002  .dluow uoy fi ,woleb em nioJ
ot dengiser er’ew erutuf ehT  .uoy fo lla
.spets llaH ytiC eht otno tuo klaw ew dna
htiw meht gnirahs dna tcaf eht retfa sraey ytnewt efil ym fo sruoh 63 gnikcuf tseizarc eht
yaw eht gnola su rof dereehc yllanosrep dah elpoep fo snezod ynam woh ta ewA
,I seoG ”?esle enoyrevE“
,rehto hcae detroppus llits eW
.emoh og ew oS — .lla retfa
.retaw eht evoba sdaeh ruo gnipeek osla saw taht
.egarag ybraen a ni dekrap era dna ,tsaehtroN eht morf gnimoc
sehcterts won enil ehT
dnabsuh ym ot nrut ot gniog ton m'I
gnittel ton er’yeht dna
,em degdun dnabsuh-tey-ton yM .tnorf eht ta
.ti snialpxe tahT .og I ,hoooooO
t'nac I os ,rebmemer ylevitca nac I tahw nwod gnitirw ylno m'I dna(
yb emoc elpoep modnaR
.ot detcepxe reve I naht reilrae sraey ytnewt saw tI
,niar eht morf tew llits si riah yM
elbiB a gnidloh nam das elgnis A
.yadot fo ytilaer enilesab eht si
.gnihtyreve sesufni taht ssenippah fo arua ediw-gnidliub eht dna
.mosweN nivaG retnE
.enil ni er’eW  .og sruoh xis
!od ot dedeen uoy tahw did uoY
.-tol- a saw ereht taht tsuJ .esle tahw rebmemer t’nac I ,krow ta ibbaR erom eno tsael ta s’erehT
,egairraM ocsicnarF naS
segairram rof dnamed ,yltnerappA
egairram xes-emas fo egruocs live eht gnitneverp ,yllacificepS
desimorp ev’yehT
,yadnuS ,yad txen ehT
.ni bmilc dna rac ruo ot kcab teg eW
”?yadnoM no desolc llaH ytiC t’nsI“
dias dna sdnah rieht pu werht yllanif truoC emerpuS eht
.cipot eht tuoba tihs lautca na sevig yllautca ohw sevorp
.esle enoyreve htiw deirram gnitteg ocsicnarF naS ta pu t’nera su fo owt eht desirprus s’ehs taht snoitnem yllausac ehs dna
.tniop siht ta sraey owt neve ton rof rehtegot neeb ev’eW
.pu niart tsrif eht
.eciffo s’royam eht ot yawrood eht tsap seog
”retaL sraeY ytnewT
.syawyna ffuts no krow dna ni emoc ot emit
neht dna selims eh dna mih knaht I
decalpsim a dah krowrepap eht esuaceb
”.ytic evol tsrif ruo s’ti esuaceb dnekeew eht rof pu emoc ot ekil ew tub
.tnereffid saw tI
.mih dna sesnel eht neewteb sevlesruo noitisoper ew elihw raen emoc taht saremac swen yna morf yawa snrut dna pu ralloc taoc sih sah eH
.su dniheb edaced a revo rof rehtegot neeb ev’ohw elpuoc naibsel eht syas ”!su rof si ti sa uoy rof hcum sa si sihT“
sdnasuoht ot sderdnuh eht dna
.emit taht ta dah I snoitome fo xim eht rof drow a t’nsi yllaer erehT
,sreehc era erehT
.senil
,edisni daeh ot spets eht pu
?ton yhW .sraey 02 tsael ta rof siht ekil ecnahc rehtona teg ot gniog ton er’ew tub
!gnol os rof no og d’yeht taht wenk eno oN !oN“
,teltnuag eht hguorht yaw ruo ekam eW
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,4002 ,ht51 yraurbeF
,yas yeht ”,od uoy fi ereh er’uoy erus ekaM“  ”.pukcaB“ ,og ew
.elpoep dna seman gnihctam tuoba sselepoh saw I wenk eh esuaceb
setis tra suoirav no xofhcaeB sa dnuof eb naC
.gninnur tuohtiw nac eh sa tsaf sa yawa seirruh
gnimrifnoc tsuj s’tI .stifeneb lagel eht morf edisa ,tnatropmi taht t’nsi yllaer egairram“
.krad gnitteg s’ti tub
.sserdda noinu eht fo
.sredluohs reh no gnidir yob kcalb dlo raey ruof a htiw
,egairraM ocsicnarF naS lagellI repuS yM“
,syug uoy was I -tsuj I .yeH“
.gnineppah saw dna ytilaer saw siht taht feilebsid etelpmoC
tsal gnol ta edistsaE ot renroc eht nrut ot tuoba tsuj ,llaH ytiC fo edishtuoS eht no er’ew elihw s’tI  .enil ni yats eW
.03:1 won s’tI .xis ecnis ereht neeb sah
”.enil -taht- ot uoy tcerid ll’yeht ,etacifitrec eht tnaw uoy fi ,nehT
,dnah ym sekahs eH
.efas er’eW .ti edam eW
peelsa gnillaf fo regnad ni dna rallip a tsniaga gninael dnuorg eht no gnittis m’I dna
ssenippah dna yoj ’srehto fo noitarbelec dna ssenippah dna yoj detartnecnoc hcum os decneirepxe reven evah I taht
.su rof nwod dna pu pmuj ”!snoitalutargnoC” gnidaer sngis htiw elpoep
emos evah t’nod I
,tuo kcip ot ysae lla er'eW
worromot rof enil ni gnitteg yrt tsuj ew dluohS“
tew si enoyrevE
.repap fo eceip a tsuj saw tI
.wor a ni syad owt rof enola tfel gnieb retfa klaw gnol doog a rof tuo god eht ekat eW
.ediug ruoy sa gnitca m’I yadot tub
.raelcnu esarhp eno fo gninaem eht edam taht ammoc
,dlrow eht egnahc ot ,si noitcif sa lufrewop sA
ecaf yM .ecnis ro erofeb efil ym lla ni
”.nwod su tuhs ot delif tog taht
.ynomerec eht od ll’ohw enoemos ot uoy tcerid ll’yeht
yadseuT no eciffo sih otni gnitteg elbuort gnivah eb lliw dnA .yadot
dneirf lacol rieht s’ehS
.ot ssecca nevig eb reve dluohs cilbup eht erus yleritne ton m’I
.doog gnikool ton saw tI
.sessentiw owt ruo fo eno si rerusaerT ytiC ocsicnarF naS ehT
.erofeb thgin eht 8 dnuora ffo deppord nettog d’taht seittoP-atroP nezod a revo dereviled
,redluohs ot redluohs ,ksed eht ta era elpoep nezod A
”.neht yb deirram neeb evah ot evresed uoy dna
.llaH ytiC ocsicnarF naS fo yteritne eht dnuora
,taht retfa sraey wef rehtonA  .emit taht
!dnekeew yaD senitnelaV ereh tem eW“
,did tI  .dessap ti fi
dnabsuh ym sa nam rehtona ecudortni dluoc I taht thguoht reven I
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
ohw ereht elpuoc tnecajda-cilohtaC a s’erehT
.lla dna yadnoM no yaD stnediserP
sredluohs reh no yrc sdneirf reH
,ecnatniauqca na htiw enohp eht no er’ew ,yad txen ehT
ylwols gnola lwarc eW
.slaiciffo gniddew nwo rieht gnirb t’ndid ohw
syawllah hguorht dna sriats edis pu dna
nosrep suomynona emos dnA
,si rohpatem retteb a htiw pu emoc yllaer reven ev’I dna ,emit eht ta ti debircsed I yaw ehT
,regnol rehtegot neeb d’taht
.rehtegot yrasrevinna ht21 rieht etarbelec ot ocsicnarF naS ni pu neeb d’ohw
.ruoh rehtona s’tI
rieht reetnulov ot dewolla era elpoep tub“
.s05 ym ni saw I litnu egairram yag lagel ees ot tcepxe t’ndid I
“-!snoooooitaludargnoC- dna ,seiteews 4 rebmuN
teg eW .noitats TRAB eht tih ot ruoh na evird eW .00:4 ta pu ekaw eW .ylrae tuo hsarc eW
m’I …tsuj I dna ,llaH ytiC ta nwod
.derif mih gnitteg dna swen eht no mih gniees stneduts sih fo eno fo stnerap eht tuoba deirrow s’eH
.nwod meht ot deganam etats eht erofeb
ni gnillac I meht dlot dna yadnuS krow dellac I
,naem I "?annaw uoy od"
eutats nlocniL maharbA eht fo otohp etihw dna kcalb gib eht fo
,naeco na ni llits erew eW
.erofeb siht tuoba nettirw ev'I semit eht lla ro koot I serutcip eht lla gnikcehc oN
yadrutaS yawa denrut nettog d’ohw enoyrevE .wenk ohW
,retaw evoba rehto hcae gnipeek erew eW
— .taht saw taht dnA
.meht rof yppah -os- si ehS .siht gnissim eb TON lliw ehs dna gniod er’yeht tahw tuoba egassem rieht nettog tsuj d’ohw
htrof dna kcab elttar dna ,tisnarT dipaR aerA yaB otno daol eW
sresuor elbbar evitavresnoc eht taht
deirram teg ot tnaw ohw elpoep eht taht
,dalg yllaer tsuj m’I
tif ot gniyrt er’yehT
”?ydaerla nwod taht tuhs ev’dluow yeht thguoht I“
stnuoc eH .yoj htiw yddig llits s’eH
evael t’nac ew dna“
”retaL sraeY ytnewT ,egairraM ocsicnarF naS lagellI repuS yM“ saw sihT     .evarb lliw
tahw no desucof erom erew gniwollof saw I sgolb eht fo tsom dna
.ylsuovren teef sih selffuhs dna em fo tnorf ni spots nam gnuoy tpircsednon a nehw
.pots llaH ytiC ocsicnarF naS eht ot yaw eht lla
.txen tuo gnimoc saw reveohw ta worht ot ecir emos nevig saw I ecno naht eroM
ti tsniaga er’ohw
ainrofilaC ni devil ew yppah tsuj erew eW
.siht lla htiw ekam ot egassem retaerg
).noos emit yna snoitcetorp boj esol ot ylekil t’nerew tsael ta ew erehw
.tnuts lacitilop a ylsuoivbo yrev saw tI
,yadot ti rebmemer I woh fo gnitnuocer etarucca
,NNC no daer d’I sa ti tuoba hcum sa wenk ylno I
si yrots s’yadoT dna
rieht htiw tuo nael stsiruot esenihC
gat gniyalp smoor nepo ediw eht dnuora gninnur erew ohw seibab esohT
s’erehT .srotsetorp on llits era ereht tub
.ti edam d’ew taht feileR
.teef ruo htaeneb noitadnuof dilos a saw ereht tub
.su fo tnorf ni elpuoc yag gnihtemos-04 eht syaS ”.erad
segairram dnasuoht ruof revo
seciffo yranoitcnuf deknar-wol fo yawllah kcab a hguorht gniog era dna sesacriats fo tes rehtona pu kcab dna egarots dna seciffo tsap syawllah tnemesab gniliec-wol eht hguorht enog ev’ew retfa s’tI  .ylerus tub
yug ynihs deriah-kcalb cireneg emos htiw
dna secalp ni lagel neeb s'tI !eniF"
elpoep eht lla dna secrof eht lla rof
.deirram saw eh erofeb ecnis
.pu nepo yeht tnemom eht slaiciffo ytic ot elpoep gnitcerid si ecnegludnI lautepreP fo retsiS A
.ecno ta ti gnikrow evah ot tliub saw ti naht erom raf
nwod gnittis m'I ,etad eht etaromemmoc/etarbelec oT
.guh a otni owt eht fo regnuoy eht elkcat ot
htiw enod er’ew neht dna ,srepap eht tog ew wonk tsuj I .yttops si yromem nwo yM .gnipeels srenroc ni pu delruc era sdik suoremuN .2191-2091 rof
yawa pets lliw eno regnuoy ehT
ti devresed ohw ,erom ti dedeen ohw
.snoinapmoc nwo ruo pu kcip ew taht
…hcihW ”!sgniht hcus od SGOD neve toN“ woh tuoba sngis rieht htiw puorg milsuM egral a gnidulcnI
ti tsetorp ot niar eht ni tuo emoc ot gnilliw ton er’yeht elihw siht od ot niar eht ni tuo emoc ot gnilliw er’ew taht tcaf eht woh tuoba
edishtuoS ot renroc eht denrut ew retfa thgir pu swohs tem reve ev’I namow lufyoj citegrene ykrep tsom ehT
evol lanoitidnocnu htiw su gnitarbelec elpoep fo sderdnuh era ereht
.7-6 tuoba emoh teg eW
,og nam ym dna em ,"tihs lleW"
.edisni dekcud dna devaw eH
.dezinagro taht lla teg ot emit dah eno on dna
,ylper yeht ”,erus hO“
.s03 yb detrats ylerab d’I erofeb
.ni ffo evird ot repmub eht ot deit snac-nit htiw etelpmoc degnarra elbitrevnoc deirraM tsuJ a teg ot deganam elpuoc enO
tneve citnehtua na ot sessentiw taht eno
.niar ot strats ti nehT
.tekcop trihs ym otni dekcut rewolf ylil gnitliw a evah I
,yadseuT noisses ni kcab si truoC emerpuS ainrofilaC eht esuaceb“
lagellI repuS yM“   yojne esaelP
elpoep fo tol a evah ew dnA
.detaluclacsim ylthgils dah eW
.troppus s’rehto hcae erew ew
.tnuts lacitilop teews yrev a saw ti tuB
ni teg t’nod eW — .diasnu seog
.edishtroN no trats eW
.elbissop sa llaH ytiC otni elpoep ynam sa
.sredluohs eht yb em koohs tub lla mom ym dna
.llah ytic ta elpoep gniyrram detrats dna ocsicnarF naS ni lagel saw egairram yag taht
.nuN dna naM elbiB ees I erehw osla si hcihw ,edistseW no er’ew nehw pu gniwohs strats tsrif azziP
gnirebmemer em tsuj si siht ylniaM .lli ro doog roF
.niar eht ni setargetnisid ti retfa sevael ehS
.pu sevlesruo eldnub eW .rewohs eW
decnuonna eh nehw
.srotsetorp fo tol a neeb dah ereht ,ynnus saw ti nehw ,erofeb yad ehT
elpoep eht ot enil eht fo dne eht morf ekoC fo nac a ssot dluoc uoY
.seenk eht ot pu sniats retaw evah stnap yM
”,rehtegot etuc oot era sdik uoY“
.yadseuT litnu nepo t’nera struoc ehT“ ,ehs seog ”!on hO“
.krowrepap lagel eht teg ot retal raey a pihsrentrap citsemod a did eW
evom ot dah ev’dluow
.elpuoc deirram a sa laem laiciffo tsrif ruo evah
.tey gniht a t’nsaw aidem laicos esuaceb wonk t’ndid eW
.ruoh na retfa pu sevig eH .t’nod esaelp ot dna gninnis er’ew lla su sllet
,ksa dna em ot txen dnabsuh ym ot nrut
.gniht nmad elohw eht gniod er’yehT .spets niam eht no tseirp eht -dna- seilimaf eritne rieht thguorb evah ot mees
dna ta ffo pots ew taht noitats eht raen rJ slraC a s’erehT  .gnivrats era ew dna 03:4 s’tI
.sredro yreviled gnikam trats enilno elpoeP
ni nemow anitaL suoirolg owT .gnippiks dna
.gninnur pots ot meht gniggeb ylsselpleh
ytriht-noon ,noon tuoba s’tI
%001 a -si- ti tuB
,I dna ebab yM
elpuoc rehtona morf tops a gnikat yllaitnetop er’eW
.tah sih ffo gnignah dna smra sih fo skoorc eht ni dekcut
truoC emerpuS etatS ainrofilaC eht taht daer ot ,yadseuT
.egamad retaw dna sseniddig fo noitanibmoc eht htiw tahw
gniht rehto siht saw ereht tub
”!ereht ti od ot evah t’nod uoy os tuo eseht llif ot
.stsucol yb deruoved neeb ro erif no thguac s'gnihton
su tsap snur edisni teg depleh ew yob dlo raey ruof ehT
gniog puorg a saw erehT
.rohtua eht fo snoitcellocer eht morf yleritne dlot
.rehto hcae ta kool I dna eb-ot-dnabsuh yM
-m’I .od dluoc uoy tahw fo duorp os m’I .uoy rof yppah os
siht teg ot enil ni su fo tnorf ni elpoep dnasuoht a tsomla era ereht
.edishtron ,yrots dnoces eht ot detcerid teg eW
retnuoc eht dniheb yug ehT
edisni s’ohw enoyna taht
.goD fo ecioV ehT no
neeb evah taht s”!UOY KNAHT“