.kaolc ym revo detfaw ria eht ni taews fo stnih htiw gninoitidnoc-ria toh dna
,tesolc eht morf gniyarts rof ssensselemoh dna ytrevop htiw su hsinup ton dluoc
,yranimilerp s’dnuor tsrif ehT
,laem yreve dessolf gnivah no detsisni stnerap ruo hteet etihw yltcefrep dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.sthgil thgirb ta decniw seyE .deretne I dna
elohw a sa enohpesreP dna—
.ecalp ruoy peek dnA
.setunim net ni si dnuor dnoceS
,mroftalp egral a otni desivorpmi gnieb reniatnoc gnippihs egral a no doots ohw ,s’nedyaC saw tI
tsuj s’teL .taht tsuj ton s’ti tuB“
.ecnaegnev a htiw denruter reilrae morf gnileef ruos ehT ”…I ,sediseB
.noitcerid sih ni worbeye na desiar I
”,nedyaC s’eman yM“
.noitcerid ym ni degrahc ssam egral a sa tsuj yawa tsiwt neht
,dnim ruoy egnahc uoy fi tuB
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.owt neht ,hgis enO
”.ssap ot dewolla eb lliw ay fo net ylnO
.eiteews ,melborp oN“ ”.araM ,sknahT“
.esiar taht teg uoy epoh I .ma I ,ylurT“
.gnidnatsrednu ni demialcxe lla eW
.esion duol eht hguorht debbats eltsihw llirhs a
”.eno dlo sih ecalper ot draugydob wen a rof gnikool si ssob ym ,eeS
,deriuqni yltneg I
.dnop natilopomsoc ssel
,hguoht edisni eht nO
,gnir gnixob a ot txen renroc raf eht ni decalP
.deretne tsal ew ecnis gnivomnu dna desolc deniamer dah hcihw ,rood moor rekcol eht ot sih htiw derednaw seye yM
,tsehc derruf-etihw ym ot resolc kaolc niar ym degguh I sa elddup yreve tsomla hguorht dehsalps stoob yvaeh yM
.noitcurtsed nabru gninmednoc elihw
.rellams ylgnisaercni werg dworc eht ,elttil yb elttiL
,gniliec eht ni deddebme sthgil hsrah eht ta deknilb I .ksam eht did os
.kniht ot emit evah t’ndid I
.elkcirt ydaets a ot nwod demlac dah mrotsniar reilrae eht tsael tA
.esle erehwemos efil gninigami dekil I
dluoC…uoy dluoc ,yllautcA“
.yad dna thgin yb dedivid ynoloc yawaraf a no sboj rof egnahcxe ni ruf rof hself dedart ohw srekrow gnieb ylekil rettal eht
.delkcuhc dirbyh cennef sseleman ehT
trapa llef gnihtyreve ,nehT
,enohpesreP fo enoz rotanimret eht no desab ynoloc lanep a ecno saw ytiC thgiliwT
.ytiliga ro deeps fo sseldrager
!dnif t’ndluoc ew seno eht neve ,lla ta snopaew on
.em dniheb gnidnats namuh ffurg a ot gninrut erofeb em ot elims elbaecitonnu na delggums eh nrows ev’dluoc I
.daeh s’eninac eht revo welf taht enord aremac gnirevoh a fo thgis thguac eye yM
.ereh meht thguorb tahw tuoba snoitseuq gniksa ro rehto hcae ot gniklat ,dnuora doots ylpmis srehtO
”,t’nod uoy fi pleh nac I
”.nwo ruo no evil su tel annaw neve t’nod yeht ekil s’tI
.hguone llew sboj rieht did
”ronaM tsercgnaF fo sluoS owT“ deltit allevon ecnamor lacirotsih a dehsilbup yltnecer osla eH .noitcif
,trap tseb eht rof ygrene gniniamer ym fo tsal eht evas ot detnaw I ,lla retfA
,hctah dekcolnu eht ssorca emac I sa em dniheb yawa raf demool yks gninihs ehT
,namssenisub a si eniamerT .rM“
.uoy ekil ,tuokrow kciuq a rof ereh tsuj m’I
.ydaer dna detardyh sevlesruoy teg os ,gnuoy llits s’thgin ehT
,noitucesorp ni tluser yam htnom erom eno nihtiw .cnI stnemtrapA repinuJ esrubmier ot eruliaF
,sgnirehtag ylimaf ta ,gnitsisni fo dnof ylekil si elcnu etirovaf tsael ruoY
,ffulf eht htaeneb deraeppasid mrof ym litnu taoc ruf ym nwod gniyrd dna emirg eht lla gnivomer neewteB
.)enim t’nerew doolb fo spord eht fo emos(
.snihs ym ot kcik a morf delbmuts ylraen I
.retrohs werg enil eht
;deniamer su fo neT
”.ehca ytsan a uoy evig ll’tI
,deknilb nexiv yppep yllamron ehT
.deneppah gnihton ,tsrif tA ”!oG“
.emod yruxul rieht edistuo
”?relaed tekram-kcalb ehT“
,gniraelc eht dnuora elcric egral a mrof ot yawa detlob tnemanruot eht fo tuo kcab ot dediced ohw esohT .ecno ta lla
.em ta gnirats ,renroc raf eht ni erugif rellams a no llef seye ym nehw yllaitnenopxe werg tI
.hguoht evloser ym dleh I
”.uoy llik ot seirt enoemos sselnu toN“
.srieht naht rehgih gnieb secirp ruo tuoba denialpmoc netfo rednu dekrow I sreganam yaW-M ehT
.thgiliwt derevoc-duolc ni dehtab epacsdnal ykcor sseldne ylgnimees a dna ,sexelpmoc tnemtrapa gniyltuo neewteb deltsen
.dehgis neht ,yldetraeh-flah dehgual I ”,ereh morf em peek ot niar naht erom ekat annog s’tI“ ”!elbirret s’ereht tuo rehtaew ehT
,)hserf emos dna ,dlo meht fo tsom(
,kcehc dnuorgkcab eht evivrus dna ,daeh level a
”.htnom siht fo dne eht yb eripxe ti tel ,tsael tA
.tekcop tnorf sih morf enohptrams sih rof dehsif eh litnu ton ,tsael tA
trihs tuokrow ytrid ym fo strap suoirav ssorca dna keehc ym no sesiurb leef dluoc I
.ffo raew ot denetaerht enilanerda eht sa ediced t’ndluoc I
,mined yddum ni sniwt hateehc fo riap a
.htraE no kcab detcele neeb dah lareneG-yraterceS wen a
”?’evitaitini etis-
.desucof ehs dna ,reh fo tnorf ni neercshcuot eht ot tnew swap der reH
.seitriht-dim sih ni namuh derit-syawla na
,rehtorb niwt a dah llits ehs fI
.gurhs dexaler erom a htiw dias I ”,yllaer toN“
,ralupop tsom eht erew senob nekorB
.hguoht regna gniworg eht nwod deleets I
.rekcol denepo nwo sih eb ot demussa I tahw tsniaga denael eh sa dessorc erew smra esohw
.stinu gnisuoh detacirbaferp erew meht dnoyeB
.lacitpeks saw I ,edistuo eht nO
”.deksa snoitseuq on ,pihsrebmem ruoy emuser ll’I
.kcans llams a retfa neve
syug hguot ebannaw dna snailivic kcehc dnuorgkcab ot reisae s’ti decnivnoc dna dionarap si ssob eht yas
,elbuort esuac t’ndid sraluger dna
.sdnoces ytnewt yreve elzzum ym tih taht regguls a ro
’.ycaripsnoc eimmoc‘ a era seititnedi dna sthgir reeuq taht
,ti detapicitna nedyaC taht demees ti ,ylikcuL
”.noos erudecorp gnidoc-ina na droffa yllanif ot tiaw t’nac I“
,daed pord ydob
,sselhtoot ylegral eb dluow aibohpreeuq roF
.reyolpme laitnetop ruoy rof nosiail a sa gnivres m’I ,thginot dna
.araM ,neppah annog toN .on ,haey tub“
.sekirts gnitnelernu
,strikstuo s’ytic ynoloc eht fo pit tsomnrehtuos eht no doots tI
.ycamrahp erots-ni eht morf emoc t’ndid taht noitacidem niap gnikat thguac saw ehs retfa derif tog rosivrepus remrof enO
.tsehc ym fo tnorf ni swap ym devaw I
.ecnarevileD thgiliwT fo OEC eht ,yllacificepS
,dnuorg ruoy peek nac uoy fi tub
.yllacitamotua ti dekcoler bmuht ym fo sserp rehtonA
.snoitatcepxe deecxe ot deganam lla ev’uoY“
.soahc otni dnecsed ot dworc eht fo tser eht gnivael
.retupmoc ksed reh ot detcennoc elconoM tramS reh yb neddih rehto eht dna ediw eye eno ,yllufreehc deppiy araM ”!emoclew ,yboT“
.revewoh ,desopxe leef em edam tnemtrapa ym edistuo gniraew toN
yrruf
.hgih dekrep srae flow htoB
,tfihs boj txen eht rof gnirevocer/gnidaerd tneps gnineve gnol a yb dewollof ,tuokrow kciuq a rof snalp yM
”,evitcirtser era selur s’noinu draugydob ehT“
?stiderc erom derdnuh-eerht ekam annog I ma woH“
,em gnihctaw yllaer erew uoy fI“
.su fo lla no nwod gnikool
,reilrae enihcam htailoG taht no drah gniog ay was I nehT
tfel taht gniddap esned ni derevoc noteleks muinatit a fo edam
.ytreporp fo eruzies dna noitcive gnidulcni dna ot pu
.enaw yllacitamard ot detrats
,neves toof xis ta tnenoppo dna
.ezirp gninniw s’tnemanruot lagelli eht mialc ot
,yldab os draugydob wen a sdeen ssob ruoy fI“
”?lagel…yltcaxe ton s’tI ?sseug em teL“
.sthgieh elbidercni rieht ta esirnus tnenamrep eht dehcuot ylerab sroolf ssalg pot esohw sreparcsyks llat neewteb skcolb lareves klaw ylpmis dluoc I
,sraey ytfif naht redlo tsael ta ro desu saw gnihtyrevE
,eninac eht ot roolf eht morf tohs seye yM
,ksed noitpecer eht fo tnorf ni gnitiaw elpoep fo enil eht ta denaorg neht
,tuo evig ot em rof dedaelp selcsum gnihca ,derutroT
.elzzum ym gnitcetorp ksam eht htaeneb derepsihw I ”,stiderc erom derdnuh-eerhT“
.srellik rof kool em gnivah ton s’eniamerT .rM“
nedyaC .esiurb ym ot regnif a gninoitom
”,yboT“ ”?sruoy s’tahW“
,rodirroc ria-nepo eht nwod srobhgien ym fo eno tuo dellac ”,yboT ,gninrom
.gnicar pots t’ndluow sgnul dna traeh ym ekil tlef osla tI
.snoitcurtsni rehtruf rof tiaW“
.msilatipac fo seitiuqeni eht rof ton fi
,dias I ekil ,woN .tnellecxE“
.ydob eros ydaerla ym degnap boj sselluos ym ot gninruter fo thguoht ehT
tsehc sih revo lla sracs htiw namuh hsiturb ,llat a
.dedda I ”,esruoc fo ,nosaer nihtiW ?snoitseuq emos ksa I naC“
.ylevissimsid wap sih devaw eH
,gnirettum deunitnoc I ,stih dilos neewteB
.seye trela ym dednilb ylraen dna elzzum ym derevoc taewS
,dratsaB mhtyhR yb daeR  .dehsinimid-hcum
.noitats ot noitatS
”?ay rof gniog efil s’woH“
.ezorf enoyreve dna ,su dnuora sreehc eht hguorht naelc decils reilrae morf eltsihw emas ehT
,raey eht ni reilrae eutats cirotsih a deyortsed sladnaV
rekcik eht morf ecnatsid tpek I dna
.tsethgirb dna tseb s’noinu taht naht
.nedyaC eb ot dezingocer I mohw fo enO
.elkcuhc citehtapmys a evag ehS
”.gig ydaets a dna ,sruoh
,sicoV sumoD yb ”sesiurB noeN“
.derednaw seye ym erofeb yawa deklaw enil ni enoemoS
”.niaga uoy ees ot eciN“
.setad lautca no yenom eht etsaw syawla nac I dna
seveiht egaw ro srekees-tner ,sessob ,seilimaf htrib fI
”!lla ta ton ,on ,on ,oN“ ”—did I ro ,enod sah ssentiF sselraeF gnihtemos fo esuaceb ti sI…sI“
.tuokrow etelpmoc a dellac eb ot hguone ton tub ,gnitfil-yvaeh deriuqer smoorkcab s’traM yaW-M ehT
.pihsrebmem myg a rof pu dengis I nosaer tseggib eht saw ti ,tcaf nI
”.tuokrow ruoy yojne og uoy ,won roF
.yrujni suoires a gniniatsus retfa tuo depmil tsoM
,yawa pmuj ot deganam I tub ,kcab ym gnola slian walc ekil-rozar rieht dehsal dah enoemoS
,hE“ ”?uoY“ .deil I ”,doog ytterP“
.em demrofni eninac eht ”,doog er’uoY“
.ssentiF sselraeF retne ot elba eb regnol on d’I
.niamer uoy fo net ylno litnu
,ytic ynoloc eht fo ytilanosrep eurt eht wonk t’ndid yeht ,niaga nehT
.ecniw a htiw tfel neht
.knuP nooccaR elowS
”.esrow era syug ehT
”?eiteews ,gnorw gnihtemoS“ .dekrep srae reH
,dworc eht dna em neewteB
.daeh level a peek ot deganam I ,revewoH
.raey siht fo hcraM fo sa cP 842,1 ewo
.hteet dewalf dah ylimaf notgnisneK eht ni ydoboN
.serutarepmet dloc yllarutannu eht ot enummi erom meht gnikam puekam citeneg rieht
,tsihcosam a gnieb no delttes I ?eM
.em gnimandaed tpek eh fi tuo sthgil s’reganam ym gnikconk yllautneve eb dluow gnixob ot emoc reve d’I tsesolc ehT
,gniraelc eht dellif ekila dedoc-yllacitsilamina dna snamuH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.hcni erem a yb em dessim tI
.sdrow ruof esoht desserts nedyaC ”,ton si eh ,oN“
llamS‘ .em kcuf…neht lleW“ ,derettum I
.tuokrow niam eht fo trap ylrae na ti deredisnoc I ,gnihtyna fI
.niard eht nwod og t’ndid tub llats citsalp eht otni delkcirt daerD
emaceb yllanif eh nehw
tnemecalper dengised ylwen a gnilievnu dna muidop a no gnidnats ronrevog s’ytiC thgiliwT htiw
.em ediseb ria eht depiws sregnif dewalC
.neppah ot gnihtemos rof detiaw lla ew sa tnaligiv gniniamer ,flesym ot tpek I
.gnidnuf eht rof elbisnopser gnieb sronod lareves denoitnem eH
.rebmun tcatnoc sih ro yralas ylraey desoporp a em nevig rehtie dah eninac suoiretsym eht fi derednow I ,tnemom a roF
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
no‘ taht tuo yrt annog ton er’uoY“
,sevolg sselregnif ,strohs hgih-eenk gniraew ,retal setunim moor rekcol s’nemow eht morf deztlaw I ecnO
gnidaer/gnitirw elihw tfihs drayevarg eht gnikrow & cisum evawropav ot gninetsil emit eerf sih sdneps ohw
.elzzum ym nwod delkcirt syawla taews dna
,em htiw tcatnoc eye gnikam nehw dereens ohw onihr a yb
.dnuorg eht ot meht dezilibommi taht ekirts kciuq a mrofrep dna
”…ssa dedoc-ina thgit ym ,’tnemanruot
.selcihev noitcurtsnoc enilffo fo noitcelloc egral a dnuora yaw ym devaew I
.ti rof gniog eno ylno eht eb t’now aY“
.erutsop dexaler s’dirbyh cennef eht tceffa t’ndid mih ta gniralg sreggad dloC
.thguoht yna dias I tahw gnivig tuohtiw deggurhs eH
.em ni remraws eht tuo gnirb ti tel I sa gnittes regguls a no nur .I.A s’htailoG eht gnittel
,taorht s’rekcufrehtom elbisnopser eht nwod etercnoc diuqil ruop yllanosrep ll’I
.snaej deitrid dna tekcaj kcalb dedooh a yb decalper erew sehtolc tuokrow siH
.nosaer emos rof eye live eht em evag eH .regnuoy ebyam
.lavir nwod derewop ym morf yawa gnipmil neht
.ereh er’ew yhw wonk lla ew kniht I“
.em detcerroc eh ”,boj a ta ecnahc A“
”?huh ,s’htiliL ot neeb reven aY“
ytiC thgiliwT elihw ,scitanaf suoigiler yb detalupop erew yeht dna
,wam ym morf loord gnipiW
,pu ekops eh ”!sesiurb dna stuc dnoyeb seog gnihton ,oslA“
.ylthgils denediw seye yM
.pu evig ot detnaw em fo trap ynit A
;serugif railimaf eerht dettops I ,ronrevog eht dniheB
,tnirp enif eht fo eceip eguh a hcus gninrael retfa detseretninu saw I yas naht rehtaR
.yadot krow ffo dellac I dnA“
,noitpecxe eht erew sronod gge dna mreps yM
,noitnem ot dediced I ,esacriats lartnec eht rof gnivael erofeB
.ynoloc siloportem ylno s’enohpesreP ssorca dop tisnart a gnikat eriuqer t’ndid tI
.tius etihw ecin a eb ot desu tahw ni desserd regit dnuobelcsum a
;swen ralletsretni ro snurer moctis gniyalp sneercs VT egral ynam fo eno ta ylderob derats I
.ssentiF sselraeF ta kcab em nevig d’eh retnab yldneirf revetahw decalper eralg suoires A
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT      ”.setunim
,elttil yb elttiL
”.thginot htiw kcul doog ,esiwrehtO
!reklats a ton m’I“
.tneitapmi erew spets yM
.seuqilc llams demrof emoS
”.s’htiliL madaM ta setutitsorp eht rO
?reffo siht s’tahW“
,nedyaC s’eman yM
staerht fo lanesra rieht dnif dluow stogib eht
,deksa I ”?htailoG taht yb dekcik ssa ym gnitteg saw I semit eht ees uoy t’ndid
,tnurg elbiduani na evag ylpmis nedyaC
,keew a semit eerht detisiv I gnidliub etercnoc eht ot emoh ym morf klaw etunim-net eht gniruD
.erus eb t’ndluoc tub noitareneg-driht ro dnoces eb ot deraeppa ohw wef a dettops I kniht I
.seiranimilerp htiw trats s’tel
,loohcs 21-K fo tuo thgiarts detaudarg drapoel ehtil a—
thgilyks ssalg eht revo tpews ria dloc eht sa teerts dedworc a nwod deklaw I
,smelborp yenom gnivah er’uoy draeh dna ,ksed tnorf eht ta araM ot gniklat uoy draeh I ,yawynA
.enil eht fo tnorf eht ot ti edam I ecno mih deteerg I ”,ereht yeH“
,gnikniht tuohtiw detcerroc I ”,’evitaitini gnisuoh etis-nO‘“
,srethgif regguls regral eht morf ecnatsid deniatniam I
.ruos gnileef dna dekan rekcol ym ot revo deklaw I ,ylnedduS
”.reffo na ay ekam d’I thguoht I dna
.trid devapnu ,tsiom tem stoob yM
.flow-ehs dedoc-ina na ot elam namuh a morf og ot erudecorp eht tog I nehW .em
.yas nac I lla s’tahT
.lanoitarepo mraf ralos tsav s’ytiC thgiliwT peek ot ylsseltneler gniliot
,skeew fo elpuoc a nihtiW
,taews elam gnimlehwrevo saw efil fo sngis rehto ot dnif dluoc I tsesolc ehT
,neercs eht morf yawa yletaidemmi detrad seye eulb ym ,gninworF
.em dniheb denioj srehto wef a dna eninac trohs a taht pleh t’ndid tI
.noitnetta etaidemmi dedeen taht stuc walc peed htiw gnola
.gnissim tnew lairt bom gnimocpu na rof ssentiw A
,elkna eht barg ot emit ni tsuj detcaer I ,yletanutroF
.rehto hcae dnuora doots snezined fo dworc egral A
”.oot ssa s’ssob eht tcetorp nac yeht sa ssa hcum sa kcik nac ohw repparcs tnetepmoc a deen eW
.sesiar su evig ot gnisufer s’traM yaW-M dna
!em teG !em teg ,nom’C“
yltnetni su dehctaw nedyaC ,elihwnaeM
,tnaem yllaer ’seiranimilerp‘ tahw etunim tsal eht ta gnizilaer em rof neeb t’ndah ti fI
.emoc d’uoy kniht t’ndid I“
,eson eht ot tih a morf kcab dekrej daeh yM ”!kcA“
.elims dereffo reh denruter I
.stod eht tcennoc ylkciuq ot em rof ylno ,esnopser a gnivig ta desuap eH .deksa I
.sruoh owt gniwollof eht rof tsixe t’ndid yehT
.esipsed uoy yaW-M taht ta krow regnol on dnA
.rats ruo otni thgiarts tibro morf dessot esproc s’rekcufrehtom emas taht evah neht
.stiderc dnasuoht-owt tog dnuor tsrif eht fo srovivrus yas did eh ,sulP
.pu edam ydaerla saw dnim ym
,rehtaew eht ro ,seirecorg ,tner
dooG“ .tnirpregnif ym daersim t’ndid dna dekcol ti erus ekam ot esnes doog eht dah llits I hguohT
.pihsrebmem ym lecnac ot uoy deen ll’I“
,enam dna eson deidoolb a htiw noil a
.emoh ta deniamer ksam elzzum dna kaolc dedooh ehT
.droldnal eht morf eciton nmad rehtonA
morf gniohce cisum esnetni dna sthgiew gnihsarc fo sdnuos eht htiw
.suoicsnocnu em gnipmots deirt dna revo em dekconk dah srethgif eht fo eno retfa ,trid fo reyal llams a did oS
,rellams a ni hsif regral eb ot iruatneC ahplA morf detargime gnivah
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tsap eht enola tel
.flesmih decudortni eh
,traM yaW-M tuoba gnikniht erom oN
.tniop egatnav sih morf su gniyevrus retfa decnuonna nedyaC ”,enod lleW“
,eye tfel ym rednu esiurb a tfel tI
,noitasnednoc morf tcetorp ot ton fI
,sicoV sumoD yb ”sesiurB noeN“
.tuo pat tsael ta ro ,nwod uoy kconk ot detnaw noitcerid yreve ni srethgif rehto nehw xob-tuo ot drah saw tI
”.rof gnikool yletamitlu er’ew tahw si hcihW
.retemaid ni erca na ylhguor saw sdrawot deklaw I emod noitcurtsnoc citsalp eht
,rood eht kcolnu ot neercs eht no mlap ym desserp ,edisa ti depiws I nehw rehtruf neve nwod desaerc elzzum eninimef ,yhsa ym no nworf ehT
,tcirtsiD siraloP eht ni krow dluow sregit ro ,sevlow ,sexof ,sraeb fo AND eht nevig esohT
.srebmun emos ni gnipyt retfa ppa rotaluclac a em dewohs dna moor rekcol deipucconu eht ssorca revo deppets eH
,sllib fo gnikniht erom on
.gnilrans ,flesym ot derettum I ”?revo em kcuf nedyaC diD“
,)eldnub a tsoc ti fi neve ,yrotsih tnecer ni syub eslupmi tseb ym fo eno(
oc sih edisgnola
,deksa snoitseuq on ,tnorfpu dnasuoht-owt teg srovivrus yranimilerP
!snoitalutargnoc ,niamer ohw esoht roF
.kcolc eht gninnur-tuo dna
.serugif gnikool-tnatropmi wef a fo tnorf ni demrof dah enil gnol llams a
.ffuts eht hcuot t’nod I“
.owt ro rednatsyb gnireetnulov a fo pleh eht htiw ,srotcod dias yb tuo deggard yllaretil eb ot dah dloc tuo dekconk esohT
.eltsihw desserpmi na tuo tel I ,eciwt neht ,ecno gniknilB
.gnihtemos hcnup ot detnaw yletarepsed I
.oot drocer suoiverp ym naht sekirts erom derocs I
.slanimirc fo stnadnecsed eht erew ohw snezitic fo snoillim dah—
dirbyh seiceps-ssorc A .ruf nat esiwrehto sih no sgnikram xof der eciton ot em del dah espmilg feirb yM ?spahrep ,cennef A .strohs kcalb gnittifmrof ylno gniraew ,em naht redlo sraey net eninac trohs A
elgnis a ees sa hcum os I fI
”.neht yawa ksA .hguone riaF“
,yad taht no rehtorb reh fo ylralucitraP
.ekoj a ta tpmetta dab a dlot I ekil
.yb deklaw I sa deggurhs eh ”,retal tfihs thgin gnol rehtona krow em gnivah era sessob eht
.degahrromeh loop yranimilerp eht sa yllaicepse ,yltnetni em dehctaw eh—
eraf lliw yboT woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,ot demotsucca werg ecno I srewoT muisylE s’ytiC thgiliwT ni smuisanmyg etavirp eht ot derapmoC
.hguone raf hsup t’ndid I taht gninosaer deirt suoicsnocbus ym tub
,dratsaB mhtyhR yb uoy rof daer
”,gnirats ton m’I“ .dereffo I
.tuokrow ym tog I ,sselehtreveN
.em htiw gninworf ,deksa araM
,185 eseilG sa nwonk ylremrof ,’nedE weN‘
”!on ,on ,oN“ ”—doG deen I em llet annog er’uoy fI
.sraey owt suoiverp eht gnirud em depleh ylniatrec yehT
.rethgiarts pu tnew erutsop yM
.tnemanruot gnithgif llams a…hu ,a gnitsoh er’eW
.snopaew yna rof gnileef ,kcab ym dnuora gnihcuot retfa deppots eH
.sdraug hteet ytsurt ym hguorht seitinecsbo erows I dna
.syaw etarapes ruo tnew ew dna ,esnopser sih tuo denword dniw yvaeh fo tsug neddus A
.yznerf eht evael ot gnitrats dedoc-ina dna snamuh fo snezod dna
.gnitoir tneloiv otni demrofsnart suneV no tsetorp naitraM-itna nA
.nedyaC ecaf ot gninrut su fo lla
.rewsna yletaidemmi t’ndid nedyaC ,taht htiW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.rof tuo hctaw ot seno eht erew seibweN
,depiws swalc ,kcurts smlaP
.erofeb gnihtyna tae t’nod tsuJ“
!odlid ytsur ay ,em teg ’n emoC“
.dnim ym fo kcab eht ot devohs erew sserts dna yrroW
”.nesohc si uoy fo eno ylno litnu enil ni txen eht tsniaga og lliw thgif a fo renniw eht ,sdrawretfA
dna nwod tnew dooh ehT
.niaga reve gnittes rexob-tuo eht esu dluoc ydobon
,rehtaew eht rettam oN
,enola htgnerts erup gnisu yb sremraws taeb netfo yletanutrofnu sreggulS
.mih dniheb dworc eht sdrawot denoitom elzzum siH
,seye eulb thgirb
.3202 ni ztiurF rohtua-
.egaugnal edurc hcus gniraeh detniaf ev’dluow sronod gge dna mreps yM
”?yllaunna diap teg I od hcum woH“
,srossergga fo aes eht ni tsol saw tnaliassa dewalc reilrae ehT
.deppird doolb dna ,dekcik sgel
.dessefnoc eh ”,ytliuG“
.sgnipparw tsirw wef a dna sehtolc tuokrow ym tsuJ
.elzzum nat s’nedyaC dessorc elims gnirussaer A ”?elpoep
:thginot rof seluR
.dnim ym dessorc thguoht tnatropmi tub yarts A
.seralg yci dna sredluohs fo ssam eht ni denioj I sa kniht flesym raeh ylerab dluoc I
.etercnoc eht tsniaga sehsurb gnidiova ro stelpord egral ta gnihsarht yllanoisacco liat derruf-krad
.dnuora lla esualppa saw erehT
.srednatsyb fo llaw eht dniheb sesac suoires eht ta kool srotcod dna scidem etis-no wef a gnivah
.thgindim saw ti dias hctawtsirw paehc ym no emit ehT
.thgin taht rekam ym tem ev’dluow I
.sduolc gniyl-wol yb degalfuomac yks tiliwt a morf secnediser roolfbus eht gnidivid
.thgiarts taht teg s’teL
.nedyaC detpurretni rethgual regae dna srumrum fo evaw A
dewollof ,separd wodniw otni tuc eb ot hguone gib sehtolc taews kcalb dna nworf tnenamrep a htiw raeb ralop a ,em saw ereht
.loS morf sraeythgil ytriht revo tenalpoxe dekcol-ylladit a no sevil detacilpmoc rieht gnivil meht fo lla
.em gniees nopu rethgiarts pu doots nexiv ralucsum a ,ksed eht dniheB .nrut ym ,yllaniF
,tner ylhtnom ym naht erom tsoc taht raewsserd gnihctam ni elamef dna elam a ,snamuh dega-elddim owt
seiceps ot deroliat srotcurtsni ssentif ro tnempiuqe evisnepxe evah t’ndid ssentiF sselraeF
,seye gnuoy sih ni tnetni live htiw drapoel ehtil eht
.tihs gnisserped yawaraf eroM
.dias eh ”,mih rof gnikrow detrats I retfa raey a ecnis toN“ ”?netfo ti sI“
.elzzum sih gnikahs ,dias eh ”,yllaer toN“
.gnicafruser deirt seiromeM
em ekil remraws a gnithgif rehtie kcuts deniamer I
,ytiC thgiliwT ni yliramirp desaB
.detiucric-trohs ydob esnet ym revo lla gnilevart tnemeticxe eht dna ,neercs s’rood tnorf ym no gnirekcilf ti dnuof I
gnir eht ni ecnatsid deniatniam htiw tnenoppo rieht gnirit yb sregguls taeb netfo srexob-tuO
,dnecsed ti tel neht ,ria eht ni wap desiar a htiw dennirg eH
.tnemom a retfa denialpxe eh
.tnemhsinup hcum sa tsuj latem fo knuh taht gnivig erew uoY“
.noertaP sih no sicoV sumoD yb seirots erom dnif osla nac uoY
.ylluferac deilper I
.taem fo skcas ekil nwod tnew meht fo detcepxe saw tahw gniwonk emod noitcurtsnoc eht retne t’ndid ohw esohT
..knuP nooccaR elowS
,daehrevo gnizzub llits enord aremac eht dettops I ,seye ym fo srenroc eht nI
.strevda noen fo edam sgnidliub dekcap ylesned ,llat dnuora dekans yehT
”.otni flesym gnitteg m’I tahw wonk I sselnu boj a rof ylppa annog ton m’I“
,tnereffid on saw yad tahT
.emoh morf yawa emoh ym deyevrus I dna
,dias yllanif I ,gnilahxE
.beW eht syawla s’ereht ,yldab os ssa dna stit ta erats annaw uoy fI“
,ssalg elttirb ekil leef smra ym edam taht sehca sulp
srethgif rehto enin tsniaga
.dedoc-ina fo noitairav a ro namuh ti eb—
”.kcuF .hgU ?sruoh eroM
.llew oot elttil a boj sti did rewohs etunim-eno eht ,yldaS
”sesiurB noeN“   yojne esaelP
.strevrep eht lla pots t’ndid ti
.tnemanruot ruo ni detseretni eb d’uoy thguoht dna
*** ”?erehw dna nehW“ ,deksa I ,yllaniF
”?huh…ll’I…ll’I ro ,liat ym gnillup neeb evah ton retteb ehcuod cennef tahT
,yllanif dna ,aneyh gnikool-derob a
.pu smra ym detfil I retfa nwod em gnittap
.roolf eht sdrawot nwod deyalps srae yM
.metsyS aryL eht tuohguorht snoitaroproc gnippihs regral htiw detepmoc ylraluger yeht
”?reyolpme ruoy s’ohW“
,sllebrab eht tub
,ruf nehsa ym otni dekac emirg ,dehca smrA
.naorg detartsurf a tuo tel I
.enilwaj dilos sih kcurts selkcunk fo riap rehto ym retfa yletaidemmi nwod tnew eH
,gnihcterts tuokrow-tsop saw tfel dah I llA
.em dniheb eninac llams eht ta gnikool erofeb krims lanif a em gnivig ,egdab .D.I ym epiws ot em rof denoitom ehS
,’stnatsetnoc‘ enin rehto eht ediseb ylisaenu doots I
.sedis lla morf deohce rettahc dna gnilleY
,deifiralc eh ,desiar swap htoB
.nwo ym no gnivil detrats I retfa yad eht ylkciuq ti tuoba denrael I
.wap sih ni dleh enohporcim a otni pu ekops eh ”?esaelp noitnetta ruoy evah I yaM“
,dworc eht otni decselaoc su fo tser eht retfa dnoces eno toN
?tif peek ot gniog I saw woH
.erafraw gnag gnilkcat eunitnoc ot dennalp tnemtrapeD eciloP ytiC thgiliwT eht ,swen lacol nI
.flesym gnivrats tuohtiw tner eht ffo yap ot hguone naht eroM
.tekram dnuorgrednu siht aiv htraE morf semag RV dna smlif-oloh detarip gniyub denoitnem netfo em htiw stfihs krow ot desu ohw rekrowoc rehtonA
llik…ot deriuqer eb I lliW“
.sciteneG-rebyC epacsadielaK fo ysetruoc gnidoc-ina llA
.rafa morf sretsop-oloh lanoitavitom emos derimda I ,daetsnI
.stinu muinimodnoc wolloh eht fo eno dnuora dekeep dna rehtruf elttil a deklaw I nehw detaropave edutitta evitagen yM
.roolfselas eht no sremotsuc lufetargnu gnitsissa dnuora devlover yllausu stfihs ym fo flah rehto eht ,sediseB
,tner ym yap ot deen I ,won thgir thgit yllaer s’yenom…tsuj I“
.smuinimodnoc egral lareves dna gnidliub tnemtrapa egral eno tsael tA
.eugalp citcalagretni na ekil dediova I taht modnoc desu a ,sulP
,suounitnoc gnisu srexob-tuo taeb netfo sremrawS ”—tihS
1 traP ,sicoV sumoD yb
.lla retfa ,ynoloc dlrow-ffo eht no morf emac uoy erehw rettam on ,nommocnu t’nerew smacS
,aera noitcurtsnoc gnorw eht otni dessapsert ylneddus d’I fi ytitnedi ym edih ot neht
.thgir ruo ot moor egral eht
”!mfH !nom’c ,knuj fo eceip gnihcleuqs-ssA
.snac ados derettil dna
gab gnihcnup a sa detarepo rednow lacinahcem eht
.setunim ytnewt ot net txen eht dellif ecneloiv sselhtuR
.deirram tog ro ,smlif lautriv wen decnuonna
.ruopnwod gniunitnoc a ees ot edistuo deppets neht
.ereh tuo gnikrow peek nac uoy woh dna ,smelborp yenom ruoy ot detaler s’tI
.nwod em hgiew dluoc taht gnihtolc roiretxe ro ,smeti elbaulav on ,yenom on ,secived trams oN
.hgual trohs a evag
.sdrow sih detaeper I ”?reffo nA“
”?em rof gnihtemos od uoy
”.od I naht erom diap teg yeht tsael tA
,seiceps rieht degnahc seitirbelec lareveS
.krow ot thgiarts tnew I
.dias nedyaC ”,eniamerT eiwoB“
”?raelc flesym ekam I oD
.metsyS aryL eht ni tenalp dnoces elbatibah eht
.reh ekil ylinnacnu kool d’eh
.deriuqni eh ”?smelborp yenoM“
reh sa regae sa tsuj
,deksa yldrawkwa neht ,dias ehs ”,hO“
.oot drawnwod dedlof srae reh ,dias ehs ”,yrros m’I“
,suomaf dna hcir s’ytiC thgiliwT desuoh taht emod eht naht rellams semit ytfif dna ,foorpdnuos yltsom ,foorprehtaeW
.ria esnet eht dellif ytiveL
.sdnert noihsaf ro ytitnedi rof dedoc-ina emoceb t’ndid yeht em
.eciov ekil-lanoisseforp tey ,peed rehtar a ni dias eh
,seiceps yreve fo snosrep dedoc-yllacitsilamina dna snamuh tsap gnidaw dna kaolc ym gnigguh
.sknird derahs rof hcum oot egrahc s’htiliL ta slrig eht dna ,em rof ton s’nroP“
,em rof hgih oot s’eef yrtne ehT“
.mih ot ,os raeppa thgim ti yhw elbadnatsrednu si ti dnA
.eciov deifilpma na yb decalper gnieb gniltsihw eht
.teef ym ta gniggaw liat ,deksa I ”?boj a em gnireffo uoy erA“
,renroc eht ni denoitats htailoG eht gnipeek sleehw ytilibom nekorb ot euD
.reilrae mih deciton d’I fi derednow I
.no esuolb deveels-gnol ym gnittup retfa dirbyh cennef eht ecaf ot dnuora denrut I
”?srieht fo noinu gib taht morf sdraugydob lautca erih ton yhw
,tnelis llef enoyrevE
saw sruo ot metsys gnirobhgien tsesolc ehT
.kert regnol a t’nsaw ssentiF sselraeF eht taht sdog knahT
.eil t’ndid I ”,ti evol ll’uoY“
.paceenk s’renwo enisru eht ot detcennoc enim erofeb tsif egral a gnissim ylworran
.ti htrow tlef ti tub
?sruoy fo seye esoht peek annaw uoy oD“
.naorg a desserppus I
,ni em democlew srood ssalg-dna-leets citamotua ehT .ti edam I
”!thgin lla evah t’nod ew ,nom’C !txeN“
”.yrros ,thgiR .thgiR“ ”.rehto yna ekil
,stifeneb taerg
”?ksed eht ta gninetsil uoy ereW“
,riah kcalb debmoC
,yap taerg a deetnaraug eb ll’uoy
derussaer gnihtolc dna ruf deitrid rieht ta ecnalg kciuq A
edisni dellatsni arb gniniart a htiw trihs-t a sulp
,tnemssarah tuoba ycilop ecnarelot-orez a detsaob ssentiF sselraeF elihw tub ,lanummoc erew smoor rekcol ehT
.rethguad gnilims rieht sulp
gniws a ekam ot meht rof detiaw neht
.nelots tnaw t’ndid I gnihtyna gnirb ton I dednemmocer dah nedyaC .srekrow oN
sthgiew dna ,sllimdaert lautriv
.taorht ym fo kcab eht depacse ffocs A
,tcirtsiD siraloS eht ni krow dluow sonihr ro ,saneyh ,shateehc ,slakcaj ,snoil fo AND eht nevig esoht ,elihwnaeM
,selkna ym tsniaga yltneitapmi gnihsiws liat ,nehT
.feiler toh fo elahxe na tuo tel I
yltnerruc dna ,tner ylhtnom no eudrevo SYAD 06 era uoy ,rednimer a sA :gninraW  2 fo
”?fo draeh ev’I ydobemos eh sI“ .deksa I
,flesym ot derettum I ”,boj dooG“
.enihcam gnixob ™htailoG IV kraM ’ssentiF sselraeF gnisu
.tsrif senim eht ni krow rehtar d’I
”.emit doog a naht tuoba yrrow ot sgniht erom tog ev’I“
.neht
.hgih sgnittes eht tes ot hguone bmud saw decneirepxeni enoemos sselnu ,lleW
.stih tcerid wef a depacse I dna ,dewollof gnigdod tfiws eroM
,raf oot selcsum ym hsup t’ndid I
.sesiurb elttil yrev
.yaw gnireel a ni ton tub ,em dessessa eH ”?os taht sI“
.tuc eht ekam t’ndid ohw srehto eht htiw dnuorg eht no gniyl ot ni evig
.tnempiuqe ot tnempiuqE
.rood tnorf ym ot enif lanimirc evissam a tnes neht
.txen neppah dluow tahw fo deifirret ro duorp leef em edam rehtie elims s’dirbyh cennef ehT