,kooh thgir taht gnireviled fo daetsnI
,edirP yppaH .stsacdop ruoy
,ytpme nwod degguhc I elttob retaw egral a ,sllip niap
.esrepsid ot detrats yeht sa dworc eht hguorht em delffuhs dna smra eros ym yb em debbarg yehT
,tsrif ekirts ot raeb ralop eht rof tiaw did eH
,srewoT muisylE fo edistuo erutnev ton did ytiC thgiliwT fo etile ehT
.dnuorg eht ffo detfil saw dna reffo eht detpecca I
.taorht eht ni tnenoppo sih deenk tub
eht tub gnihton tcepxe lliw I
.desuma kool t’ndid dirbyh cennef ehT
.eslupmi tuohtiw gnikcatta—
.ffo trihs ym detfil I ,tnenoppo tnegru-won ym morf ecnatsid dah I sa noos sa dna ,dnim ot emac aedi nA .oot diputS
.gnivom detrats enisuomil ehT
.tuo dnuof reven I
aiv deraeppa remit cihpargoloh rehtona litnu t’nsaw tI
.neT .nevelE .evlewT
,dnuorg eht sdrawot htuom sih morf sregnif dereves s’namuh roop eht taps raeb ehT .did ylniatrec I
,tnenoppo sih gnidnilb fo ygetarts emas eht demrofrep eh
yrruf
,regit nairebiS a saw emussa dluow emos tahw ,enilef dedoc-ina llat A
,niaga dellirhs eltsihw eht retfa ,hguoht esirprus ruo ot hcuM
.sih otni kcab sreggad gnirats morf revaw t’ndid seye eulb yleets ym
,og tel I dna ,ria eht ni esor dnah denniks-yarg A .ruoF .eviF .xiS
.eniw der fo ssalg a deruop eniamerT .rM ,rab ybraen a morF
.knuP nooccaR elowS ,dratsaB mhtyhR yb daeR
.retfa noos stiderc desimorp rieht htiw gnivael
,yletarapes stnenoppo rieht thgif ot detnaw rehtien
.pu srae sih dekcoc eH
.sepirts sih sa kcalb sa tius ssenisub evisnepxe na ni
.drawrof egnul gnitib a ekam ot deirt raeb ralop eht sa lrans evisserpxe na edam aneyh ehT
.derebmemer I ”!oot dennab dnA
.gninworf ,mih ta dekrab I ”,esidnahcrem no tniap gniyarps erew uoY“
,yadhtrib htneethgie ruoy no tuo devom uoy taht wohs sdroceR“
,no kcab enohporcim sih denrut dirbyh
”?hctib-eh ,em ezingocer t’noD“
.edils a otni dehcnual I
,gnithgil roiretni eht ot sknaht tub ,tsrif ta doolb fo em dednimer tI
”.seeyolpme laitnetop morf rewsna na tcepxe I ?lleW“
,emit tsaL  .gninniw fo
.knird a em gnidnah ,deksa eh ”?egnellahc txen siht ot pu uoy erA“
,noos gniriter s’draugydob tnerruc ym ,woN
.seye neerg sih ni kool dliw a dna
.traM yaW-M llams a ta etaicossa selas leveldim a gnimoceb erofeb tnemtrapa moordeb llams a otni devom neht
.remit neddus a ni tluser t’ndid ti ,dnuor suoiverp eht ekilnU
,ekim eht otni derelloh nedyaC ,niagA
.em dehcaorppa onihr eht sa sdaeh ruo revo gnirevoh enord eht
.slewej ylimaf eht htiw dedilloc woble ym dna ,sgel sih neewteb deknils ydob rellams yM
”!gnir eht otni neves rebmuN“ .em gnidulcni
.yawa deklaw ev’dluow I ,oiranecs yna nI
.sesimorp yna ekam t’nac I
namuh eht deciton I tub
.opmet ni esor su dnuora gnituohs ehT .sdnoces neetfiF
.drapoel taht ot derapmoc nameltneg rettu na saw eH
cennef eht ,setunim evif retfA
,tnemanruot gnithgif lagelli eht fo seiranimilerp eht evivrus ot deganam trahraE yboT
.sedis lla morf gnimoc ’hctib-ehs‘ fo gnitnahc dna gnippohw duol eht yb tuo denword tog ria rof gnipsag siH
.tuo yalp dluow ygetarts eht fi ees ot detnaw em fo trap A
,nirg desuma na otni demrof nworf siH
,ecalp otni kcab htoot denesool ym devom I ,eugnot ym gnisU
.niav ni erew em dnahkcab yldnilb ro ffo em ekahs ot stpmetta siH
,sdrawkcab welf I sa elzzum nehsa ym gnola deralf niaP
.evislupmi dna detanidroocnu saw nalp gniwollof eht ,thgisdnih nI	         .sdnoces
.redrah nwod dezeeuqs I
.gniciton em tuohtiw yb tnew setunim neT  2 fo 2 traP
.efil rehtona morf nosrep tnereffid a eb llew sa thgim eH“
.dessim dna gnuws eh ,noitseuq sih ot dnopser t’ndid I nehW
.dworc gnidnuorrus eht morf yawa deppets aneyh gnikool-derob ehT
.trihs tuokrow deitrid ym em gnidnah ,dias eh ”,thgif dooG“
.dne no thgiarts dnats ot ydob ym no ruf fo riah elgnis yreve dna lruc ot liat ym desuac ti ,gnihtyna fI
.deddon I ”.thgif dooG“
.seeyolpme ym lla rof detcepxe si taht ronoh dna ,ytingid ,tcepser eht htiw detaert eb ll’uoy tsael ta ,eciffo eht nI
.desseug I ,serusaem ytiruces erew yehT
”!dratsab gib ay ,ahctoG“
ma I“ .daed saw nos ylno rieht ,meht oT
sdrow eht tuo edam I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.klat llams emos egnahcxe ot deganam wohemos eW
.dnik ni denruter yllufecarg tnenoppo dedoc-ina-non s’regit eht
,thgif ot nrael ot
.rehto hcae tsniaga enola tel
.ti detcepxe ev’dluohs I
,tlah a ot deddiks eH
.tuo stug sih ekup ot nachsart a sdrawot gnilbmuts retfa mra na devaw regit eht ,retal sdnoceS
,notgnisneK eiraM dna hanoJ setilaicos enohpesreP fo noS ?notgnisneK nimajneB haiboT
.doolb fo strups llams sa llew sa ,niap gnileef ta delworg I
.emit gniwols kcabdeef eht
”?flesruoy tcetorp rO“ ,deksa eh
.suoregnad leef etile detcetorp eht edam revetahW
,sicoV sumoD yb ”sesiurB noeN“
eltneg/tneitap/ecin erew ohw sreeuq eht"
.hsiw rieht meht evag I ,oS
.em deregna ti hcum woh ees mih tel t’ndid I tey
duorp eb ot thgir yreve evah ew dnA
.deretne I litnu srac nwo rieht rof og t’ndid sdraug ehT
,drow-c eht fo snoitairav lareves em dellac
,raeb ralop eht fo tnorf ni doots eh sa noitnetta tpar ,suoesuan htiw dehctaw I
.sdrow txen ym htiw delbmuts I ”,seY“
enutroF	         .og ot tsal-ot-dnoces eht em gnikam ni rovaf dewohs ytied revehcihw deknaht I
.erafraw gnag lacol tuoba noitaluceps dna
.swalc sih gnisu deirt eh ,niagA
.denrecnoc-flah dna deyonna-flah ,deksa I ”?uoy wonk I oD“
.onihr eht elgnarts ot detrats dna ,trihs ym fo sdne htob gnipsarg ,kcab sih otno flesym dehcnual I
.yrotciv ydoolb s’raeb ralop eht rof dereehc dessentiw d’yeht tahw tuoba erac t’ndid ohw esohT
;deraperp saw drapoel eht ,os nevE
.rehtegot meht deknilc ew dna
”.citcat ytrid taht rof yrroS .sknaht dnA“
.em gniees nopu yldeticxe rrup ot demees ohw
,swalc enilef sih fo epiws gnissim ro hcnup detpmetta hcae roF
.R.E eht ot nekat gnieb em ni tluser dluow mih morf hcnup laturb enO .evissam saw eH
.srekoolno ot gnignoleb swap modnar gnittih sredluohs ym
.doolb leef dna llems dluoc I
..knuP nooccaR elowS
,dratsaB mhtyhR yb uoy rof daer
.dnuorg sih dleh namuh eht
hsiw htaed a dah I rehtiE
.su gnidnilb tuohtiw roiretni eht etanimulli ot hguone thgirb tsuj gnithgil level-wol eht morf llet dluoc I
”.boj eht rof pu er’uoy kniht ot smees nedyaC“
,ti detapicitna I
,deracs eht morf tnereffid yletelpmoc
hT“ ”.lufecruoser etiuq dna ,evisserpmi
.ti ekam annog ton s’eH
.noisiv ym ssorca decnad srats thgirb dna stod kcalb sa gniyaws daeh ym
”,laturb saw taht ,lleW“
.eltsihw eht rof tiaw t’ndid enam deniats-doolb a htiw noil ehT
.meht evah t’ndid eh ,txen ehT
,hguot emoceb ot esoohc ton did eW ".srekcufrehtom
ym fi ,srewoT muisylE ni neve ro ,devil ew
.noissucnoc desongaidnu na ro
.sredluohs sih revo gnignah remit eht htiw toN .t’ndluoc eH
,edir tisnart yaw-eno a ,esactius dekcap a nevig gnieb neht
”?seiceps gnignahc uoy fo evorppa t’ndid yeht ti ekat
.hgiht ym otni gid ot nwod dehcaer swalc sih dna ,tuo deglub seye s’drapoel sseleman ehT
.ylkciuq tsinogatna rieht nwod ekat dluoc ohw rethgif a detnaw reyolpme laitnetop yM
.ria eht otni hgih wap a desiar dna eenk ym fo og tel eh ,tsal tA
,ecnatsid ediw a peek dna od d’I tahw did eH
”?em tuoba taht dnim t’nod uoy ,oS“
.tixe s’emod noitcurtsnoc eht rof thgiarts tnew yeht sa stnuat ro stlusni gnituohs ,siht ekil t’ndid srehtom rieht dna enoyrevE
.ylper ym emac ”,dnatsrednu I“
.larutan tlef egdod yM
.srae toh-gniliob ,dnuor sih otni dekrab I
.neveS .thgiE .eniN
.hcnup elgnis a evig ot emit evah t’ndid raeb ralop eht erus edam eh ,rehtaR
.su neewteb noihsuc eht tsniaga gniggaw liat dna hgih srae sih
”!gnir eht otni eerht rebmuN“
.revocer ot ecnahc a mih evig ton did I	         .sdnoces
.su neewteb ecaps dray-net eht ssorca deddon ylmrif I sa gnitcaer ton ,desum eh
,raeb ralop eht tsniaga dnuorg sih dleh aneyh eht ,esirprus s’enoyreve ot hcuM
”,siht ot drawrof gnikool neeb ev’I ,yllaniF“
;ylkciuq os deneppah lla tI
I od esle tahw dna ,trats I od nehW“ .ylthgirb dennirg I
,dnuos dna efas m’I erus ekam annog uoy era ylno toN .uoy morf tseb
,kcab daeh sih deppans raeb ralop eht ,nehT
yehT…sronod gge dna mreps yM“
.dessim dna gnuwS
.dekcolb noos erew taht sekirts sseltneler gnivig detrats eh sa ssih s’drapoel eht tuo gninword esion rieht ,dworc eht did oS
.enim ot tcennoc t’ndluoc sgel tsaf esohT
.enilef redlo eht ta leets sa dloc werg neht dna derevaw ezag yM
”!gnir eht otni thgie rebmuN“
.gnixob fo dnuor raluger a ni ekil toN
,hguoht laturb os eb dluow stnerap ym kniht t’ndid I ,esruoc fO
skool sihT“ .gnitaes ralucric eht no serutaef railimaf eht ta ewa ni erats neht
’!?ti tuoba elitsoh os eb syawla ot evah syag eht‘ yhw ,rennid ylimaf emos ta ,deksa neeb evah llew yam uoY  .noertaP sih no sicoV sumoD yb seirots erom dnif osla nac uoY .3202 ni ztiurF rohtua-oc sih edisgnola
.eralg gums rehtona em gnivig erofeb ton tub ,drawrof deppets drapoel ehtil ehT
.enohporcim sih otni dekrab
attuo teG“   .bulC gnixoB ratS-llA s’ymedacA muisylE ni deniag ecno I tahw ot erapmoc t’ndluoc tleb sih rednu dah drapoel eht ecneirepxe revetahW
yM	         .em tih ot gniyrt niaga ,detnurg eh ”!tuo pat
.srekoolno fo llaw eht tsap deppets reilrae morf raeb ralop eht sa ,regit gnitimov eht denimaxe scideM
”?em tcetorp ot ytiliba ruoy htiw erefretni ti lliW“
.gninaorg dna revo dehcnuh
.shtaerb trohs neewteb yas ot deganam eh
siH	         .nroh regnol eht morf ekirts a ot pu flesym nepo ot ylnO .ecaf neve ro ,mra
.em gnitadimitni deirt eh
,uoy gnireffo m’I boj eht no secidujerp hcus yna teem reven ll’uoy
.tniop eno ta ecaf ym htiw dedilloc tsif
.daeh eht fo kcab eht ni dewoble dna taorht eht ni deenk gnieb erofeb niorg dna ,hcamots
,slavir ,seimene yM
.slanimirc gnihsad fo stiolpxe lanimirc eht gniyalpsid devol slennahc swen eht ,llitS
.noitcaer ym deziniturcs seye eulb yci siH
,esac eht revetahW
.detroter yledins I
.yxalag eht ssorca stekram kcalb no tnemges swen a gnirud nwohs tohsgum ecilop a ni saw ecaf denedrah s’eniamerT eiwoB gniees dellacer I emit ylno ehT
”.ereh morf yawa elim a tnuc ekaf ruoy llems nac I“ .dias eh
.ti no nettirw enin rebmun eht htiw repap fo eceip a sa llew sa
.elbisaef regnol on ti edam swalc fo epiws a litnu esnefed ni pu smra sih dleh aneyh ehT
,cirbaf eht niur ll’uoy yrrow ot hguone ton tub ,si tI“
nedyaC ”!ydaer teg ,owt dna eno srebmuN“
,elap yllarutannu niks—
.redneg tcerroc ym yb em gnillac rof mih deknaht tsomla I ”.eilrig ,ti tog uoY“
.hsalf a ni deneppah lla tI
”!yssup ,uoy ot hctib-ehs s’taht dnA“
.retsaf saw I tub ,sbir ym ot detcennoc ylraen woble nA
.rehtegot selkcunk sih gnidilloc erofeb deffuh eh ”,yssem teg sgniht erofeB
,shtaerb rieht dleh enoyrevE
,fles eurt ym desserppus dna ,deiduts
,s’drapoel dibar eht htiw detcennoc seye deworran yM
,trid eht otni llef raeb ralop ehT
.tnemgduj ym gniduolc hsur enilanerda eht no ti emalb dluow emoS
”!uoy kcuF !sevlesruoy kcuf og ,hO“
,dias eb dluoc ylper a erofeb tub ,deddon I
,dnuorg eht ot llaf ot ton rewoplliw esnemmi koot tI
”!namow a eb ot gnidneterp
.os dias snoitpircsed boj rieht sselnu ton
,emit tsrif eht roF
.nac uoy elihw ereh attuo teg tsuJ“
.dias eniamerT .rM
,puorg ecnarevileD thgiliwT eht si os tub
.seiranimilerp eht evivrus ot did I gnihtyreve retfa toN
,mih ot tnecajda taes eht sdrawot daeh enilef daorb sih fo noitom a edam eh ,nwod kcab gnittis elihW
.gnol oot erats ot ton flesym delliw I dna ,smra derit ym no demrof spmubesooG
,niks ym htaenrednu deliob doolB
.drawrof em gnilleporp erofeb srae ym ni demaercs yehT
ytnewT	         .ecneidua citehtapmys ,gnihctaw ruo did oS
,yldesufnoc erats ot em desuac tI
,kcab ym no skram walc eht pu hctap scidem etis-no eht fo eno gnivah retfA
,neves ot nwod ylneddus tnew sregnellahc eniN
,regnif eht em evag ylereM
.trela em gnipeek wam ym ni etsat reppoc eht
.htrae ytsud eht ot em htiw nwod knup eht gnignirb daetsni
pu dleh eH ”.rehtegotla snoitcurtsni derongi ro
.lamina derenroc a ekil erom gnitca detrats drapoel etarepsed eht taht enord eht
,retal setunim decnuonna nedyaC
”!tuo pat gnikcuf ot dias I !tuo paT !tuo paT“
,gnissim ,hcnup a detpmetta eH
.edisni era ylurt yeht ohw fo esuaceb nwo rieht dracsid reve dluohs tnerap oN .ma ylurt I“
.kcen ym fo edis eht nwod delkcirt taews lufdaerd ,dloc A
.daor eht ni deddebme kcart latem eht ffo derevoh taht enots naidisbo ,htooms a gnilbmeser ledom wen keels A
?peerc siht saw ohW
.yawa mih devohs I
.mih morf emac eciov ehT
.taps I ”!namow a ma I“
.neercsno saw revetahw deyevrus neht ,telbat a
.ytiC thgiliwT enola tel
.elzzup a ekil em gninimaxe ,telbat sih morf daeh sih detfil regit eht
,dne eht ni redisnocer ot desufer yltnamada sniwt eht ,llitS
.srae sih otni detuohs I ”!tuo paT“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.negyxo sa yllarutan sa tuo dewolf drow elgnis ehT ”.seY“
.now eb nac ti taht ecnarussa si
?erofeb mih nees I daH
.noinu laiciffo eht fo edistuo draugydob a gnieb fo egdelwonk dna gniniart lluF
,sregguls ekil thguof srelwarb htoB
.keehc ym no hctarcs walc prahs a evael ot ylno
.tsael ta ,edisni gnippets erofeb no kcab trihs ym tup em tel yehT
.was yeht tahw ta depsag ro dehcnalb enoyrevE
.dias eh ”,yaW-M taht ta kcab krow uoY“
”,hctib-eh ,yaW-M ot kcab og dna ereh
.hguone tsaf yawa llup t’ndid eH
”?taht kniht uoy sekam tahW“
.stsif desiar ym gnisnet erofeb gurhs a dengief I ”.yllaer toN“
,niaga ecno deraeppa remit cihpargoloh A
.em denimaxe eniamerT .rM
.snoitom dibar htiw ydob sih gnikahs detrats eh sa neve toN
,sdnocesillim ni em ta flesmih gnulf yllacitcarp eof drapoel yM
,thgif eht esol ot mih desuac t’ndah eltsihw eht gnidragersid fI
ytnewT	         .ecnal gnicnef a ekil drawrof nroh sih tsurht dna nwod nael ot mih gnicitne
”—ohw knup elttil das a tsuj er’uoY“
”?sey ,trahraE yboT s’eman ruoY“
,sehcnup gninruter ym ni yls dna seot ym no elbmiN
”.eniamerT eiwoB er’uoY…er’uoY“
”,owt uoy ,tneitapmi yrev gnitteg si eniamerT .rM“
.gniylf detrats stsif rieht dna ,welb eltsihw s’nedyaC etunim eht dereehc snezoD
.smra sih ni rewop eht nwod raew ot detrats selkcunk
.em dniheb desolc rood edis regnessap eht ,nehT
.omil eht fo dne rehto eht no gnittis erugif dehcnuh a ot detrad seye yM ”.ssim
.gniraelc eht deretne regit detius dna namuh eturb ehT
”,dah ev’uoy yssup yna naht retteb s’eniM“
.erusserp rehtruf deilppa mra ym sa gnissih dna gnilrans ,gnilggurts deirt eH ”!tuo paT“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”!gnir eht otni enin rebmuN“
.dedneffo raeppa mih was I
.gnorw on od dluoc ohw dlihc nedlog rieht saw eolhC tub ,nos tcefrep eht detnaw
”…dnuof yeht tahw revo kool ot tog reven I dna
,kcab derats noitcelfer desiurb yM
:detacilpmoc ton si rewsna eht dnA
.ecnedifnoc ym tsoob ot elttil did pu mih gniziS
.thguoht I !stnioj eht dnA
,sevlesmeht mih detaert ro latipsoh a ot namuh elbaresim eht thguorb yeht rehtehW
rof dna ,egats lanif eht ot ti gnikam no snoitalutargnoC“
na gnieb em tuoba sbaj laudividni dna sllactac htiw gnola ,esion dnuorgkcab ot dedaf su dnuora sreehc ehT
.enola enim rof dna
,sicoV sumoD yb ”sesiurB noeN“   yojne esaelP
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.selkna ro swap ym htiw ti eb—
.namowsnart ’desopxe‘
.dnah delkcunk-ydoolb a dednetxe neht
”!nom’C !hctib ,nom’C“
.sdnuow sih naht erom edirp sih esrun ot ylbamuserP
.srovivrus emoceb ot
,stnioj dna stnioP
”?namow a sa yfitnedi uoy oD“ .deksa eh
,gnihtyna em thguat reve snossel gnixob evisnepxe ’srewoT muisylE fI
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.muh tfos a htiw em rof ediw denepo ti fo noitces egral A
.noen gniremmihs detrats ti
.s’raeb ralop reilrae eht ekil sehtolc esnemmi erow dna thgieh ym eciwt revo derewot eH
”?em ezingocer uoy oD“
,tcaer dluoc enoyna erofeB
,dereehc yltneuqesbus enoyrevE
.niaga em ees ot detnaw reven yeht devorp taht drac ym ot ecnawolla lanif a dna
”,yboT ,taht tuoba raeh ot yrros
.gnihtyna yas t’ndid eH
.raeb ralop dna namuh eht demrofni eh
.sessenkaew ees ymene ruoy tel reven ot saw ti
.snoihsuc tevlev tfos eht tem dne liat ym tnemom eht ecno ta lla dehca gnihtyrevE
.selur dradnats htiw hctam gnixob a ezinagro t’ndid reyolpme s’nedyaC taht emahs A
.sepor eht uoy wohs ll’eh tub
.delbmeser I seiceps flow eht ekil gnidnuos
.krims luftcepser a otni dehprom reens siH
,reilrae ykcul tog uoY“
,letraC sdrapoeL deduolC dedaerd eht ,sordnasselA eht
.trons truc a tuo tel eH ”!evah rO“
nosmirc deird detniap elzzum derruf-etihw sih
”ronaM tsercgnaF fo sluoS owT“
.em sdrawot llormaets ot etatiseh t’ndid eh esuaceb
cisum evawropav ot gninetsil emit eerf sih sdneps ohw
.em gninwosid ni ,suollac os
.nekat saw tiab
.gnirevawnu elims sih
”,redneg gnignahc dna seiceps gnignahC“
neht ,rehcterts a no ton fI
.reverof efil ym egnahc dluow taht noisiced A
:syas brevorp derever eht sA .toir a si
ehT	         .sarb strops rof evoba sdog eht knahT
”!gnir eht otni net rebmuN“
.em ot emac nem s’nedyaC fo wef A
?thgin eht fo dne eht yb eceip eno ni tuo klaw ehs lliw
.retsiger t’ndid sreej dednuofbmud dna ,stuohs desufnoc ,sllactac
.lacigolohcysp ro lacisyhp ti eB
,mih ta nwod taps drapoel ehT ”!hctib neeY“
.pans namuh mlac yllamron eht ekam ot demees ti dna
.buts a otni devahs neeb ev’dluow eson sih fo dne eht ta noisurtorp deneprahs eht ,esiwrehtO
.dnim ot emac thguoht yarts A ”.edisni
.eil a eb dluow ti tub
.sparts tsirw ym gninetsafer retfa dias I ”,ebyaM“
.wap tfel ym ni trihs tuokrow ym gnippirg ylthgit ,oot did I
,elbativeni si thgif eht fI
.srae ym ni deretsiger ’hctib-ehs‘ gnitnahc elpoep dna sreehc fo sdnuos ehT
,kooh thgir a dengief I ,hcihw gniruD
.setunim nihtiw htabdoolb a gnitcepxe
.dworc eht otni sdrawkcab gniylf mitciv despalloc sih tnes hcnup dilos rehtona sa raor dehcnerd-doolb a tuo gnittel
,tsehc eht ni kcurts eb ot mih rof hguone aneyh eht gnidnilb
.efil dedoc-ina sih ni yad eno tcirtsiD siraloS eht ni dekrow reve eh fi derednow I
ekirts ydaets a dial I emit hcae redrah neve dereggats ylbisiv seenk siH
,htnom tsal nuf gnivah erew seiddub ym dna eM“
.kcab eralg prahs nwo ym evig neht
,esrow rof ,retteb roF
gnidaer/gnitirw elihw tfihs drayevarg eht gnikrow &
.detroter eh ”,os epoh I“
:hguoht rovaf a em oD“
.tiolpxe ot etatiseh t’ndid namuh eht gnihtemoS
.daeh sih fo kcab eht ot skcik sseltneler gnivig detrats aneyh eht retfa wap a gnisiar dna gnikohc llits
.dnah thgir sih no sregnif dah namuh eturb eht ,etunim enO
.waj eht ni mih dehcnup I dna ,epiws dnilb rehtona edam eH
.esicerp dna deniart erom ,oot redlo saw I
.deplug I ”?notgnisneK eolhC ,rethguad rieht fo rehtorb niwt dna
,nedyaC htiw noitasrevnoc dehsuh rieht morf maelg ot elba erew ew tahw morF
.gninnigeb eht morf flow-ehs sselpleh
*** .sseug dluoc I tub ,erew sdrow gniwollof s’onihr eht tahw raeh ot elba t’nsaw I
,ekim eht otni derelloh nedyaC
.tuo gniklaw htob er’uoy ro ,dnuor siht dnE“
.dehgual aneyh ehT ”!ahA“ .drah yreV
”!gnir eht otni xis rebmuN“
.gnorts tlef gnar eltsihw eht erofeb kcatta ylneddus ot egru ehT
ehT	         .sdnoces evif-
”.kcab dloh ’nikcuf t’nod
timmoc ylluf t’ndid rehtie sregnellahc eht ,stnemanruot eseht fo eno dleh nem ym emit tsal ehT
,ytilitsoh ecaf ot tub eciohc on dah evah ew
.gniniart ni pag ylekil a dewohs gnitnap derit dna ylleb reeb neddih sih ,revewoH
desu uoy taht eurt ti sI“
.nedyaC ot ylbamuserP
.taorht sih ni ria gniniamer eht htiw tfel gnirepmihW
”.deneppah tahw erac t’ndid I…I .ot dah I
.tsiser ot yrt em tel neve t’ndluow yeht
yas dluoc I hsiw I“ ,em dlot eniamerT .rM ”,woN“ .deggaw liat ym dna ,eerf tel saw egatsoh dleh hgis A ”.em rof hguone dooG“ .deggurhs ylenani eH ”.oN“ .niaga kool yleets taht mih evag I
.srekoolno deifirroh wef a tih doolb gnitriuqs kniht I
.yltcefrep snoitcurtsni dewollof
,yxalag eht ni ytirar a erew sdrapoel dedoc-ina ekil t’nsaw tI
,ytxis morf nwod gnitnuoc detrats tI
.sosrot ruo neewteb dehsarht liat depirts a sa dnuora delialf wap eerf siH
.uoy sdrawot luftcepsersid eb lliw emoS
,lagelli gnihtyna od uoy ekam t’now I
.flesym ot derumrum I ”,evisnepxe
ytroF	         !hguoht emit hguone t’nsaw erehT
”.erudecorp esahp-owt a rof deksa dna eciffo s’epacsadielaK ot tnew I litnu eman taht yb tnew I ,haey tuB
.detserra su gnitteg yb thgin ruo niur ot dah ay neht
.ygrene detsaw taht sgniws dessim ekam eof regral eht gnittel
.sregnif eht devas scidem etis-no eht fo enO
.raf os gnitteg retfa yllaicepse ,ekat ot noitpo lataf a eb dluow gniyL
”!sdnoces ytxis evah uoY
”.ytic siht tuohguorht evres ew sremotsuc eht dna ,seeyolpme sti
.elzzum derruf-etihw a otni tsif a detcennoc neht
,lairetam ylnevaeh eht gnola bmuht a gninnur morf flesym pleh t’ndluoc I
,em tsap edils mih tel I dna ,degnul eH
”.nac yeht yaw yna uoy truh ot etatiseh t’now seilla laitnetop dna ,sknup
,pley dednuow a tuo gnittel rebmemer I
.thgisdnih ni ,ekatsim gib A
,rehtaf duorp a ekil em ta dekool eniamerT .rM ”?ngis
kcatta eht egdod eh did ylno toN
,htraE no kcab etacidnys avonarreT eht sa hcuS
.niaga ,gnicafruser nageb seiromeM
.ssalg ralucric ym edisni gnihsols diuqil der eht ta nwod derats I
.yawyna epacsadielaK ot tnew dna erac ’nikcuf t’ndid I ,tniop taht ta ,neethgie denrut I nehW .fles laer ym
,delggurts I nehw yhtapmys orez tog I
,elkcac gnikcom a tuo tel drapoel ehT
.noitaborp ruoy os ro raey txen eht redisnoc tub boj siht now evah yam uoY“
.em rof ton tub ,tsom rof noisiced retrams A
.emod noitcurtsnoc eht edistuo gnittis enisuomil dekrap a ot nekat saw I
,nom’C“	         .sdaeherof dna smra ruo ffo welf taewS .sdnoces ytfiF
em r tfel s'taht lla htaed ot deillub ro tohs tog lla
.namow dam a ekil gninnirg pots t’ndluoc I ?eM
.yawa derevoh taht enord aremac eht neht
.did yletaidemmi ygetarts s’drapoel eht gnirongi neht
,ytiC thgiliwT fo tser eht debrutsid taht hctam gnituohs a ot em del tnemtrapa ruo ot erudecorp eht morf emoh gnimoC
!stniop erusserp eht rof oG .desivorpmi I ,oS
.ekops I sa yawa tnew tlef I ssensuovren revetahW
.noitcerid sih ni gnioob ecneidua eht fo srebmem wef a ta sregnif elddim deppilf neht
:detpecca ylregae I smeti eerht em evag yeht
”!neey ,ecaf ’nikcuf ruoy ffo thgir elims taht ecils annog m’I“
,ssalg dellif nwo sih tuo dleh eH
.edih ym no ruf eht htiw dne no doots selkcah yM
.gnihtyna em dlot stnemtrapa tsellams s’tcirtsid eht rof snoitacilppa detcejer
.riahc revoh s’emoh noitatilibaher a ni
.tuo dellac eh ”?tey enod aY“
”!kcA—flow-eh ,ynnuf yreV“
.hctam gnixob a ni t’nerew ew taht flesym dnimer ot dedeen I ,niaga nehT
’tes dehctam a era ew‘
erew uoY .evivrus ot koot ti revetahw od ot gnitatiseh ton
.yrasrevda regral sih gnirit fo sepoh ni gnol oot tuo thgif eht gard ot ton hguone trams saw aneyh ehT
osla uoY“ ”.uoy desserpmi I raeh ot yppah-h m’I“
.swalc sih htiw elpmet ym gnittih ylworran
.tnemugra s’rethgif elamef eht ni
.drapoel eht ta gnitniop dna gnihgual emos htiw
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
:eman tnereffid a yb og ot
,oot did I nehw hgih swap dehcnelc rieht desiar srekoolno lareveS
.gib tsuj t’nsaw eH
.ylraelc ,sehcnup worht ot woh wenk tius ssenisub deniur eht ni regit ehT
.ekam yletamitlu d’I noisiced eht detciderp evah dluow notgnisneK haiboT fi derednow I
,nwod delkcirt doolB
.srekcufrehtom hcaorkcoc ffo-dessip rehto eht &
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,liater ni kcab ffo retteb er’uoY“
”.em taeb t’nac uoy wonk htob ew tub
.reggats enisru egral eht edam niorg eht ot kcik A
.tsif gnidnecsed a htiw dedepmats onihr gnirewot eht dna ,hguoht snalp rehto dah eltsihw ehT
,drawnwod ti gnidneb dna tsirw sih gnihctans
,tsirw eht ni mih gnikirts deirt I neht
,emoh rieht ni toN
.gnir tfihsekam eht otni kcab gnitteg enoyna tuohtiw
.eson dereksihw sih gnittih eenk thgir ym
.deilper I ”,eniamerT .rM ,uoy knahT-
.oot snroh sih tub ,thgiew dna thgieh sih fo egatnavda koot ylno ton onihr ehT
.srenroc gniliec eht ni deddebme sterrut ynit dettops I nehw kcab ym pu tnew llihc suovren A
tekcaj dedracsid sih tuohtiw elbisiv erom sracs sih dna ,denifed-llew specib
.rehtona ot tops elbatrofmoc eno morf pu gnitteg detsetorp ydob ym hguoht nevE .deilpmoc I dna
.demrifnoc I ”,rehtie sredneg gnignahc em fo evorppa t’ndid yehT“
,og tel t’ndid I tub ,tuo evag seenk yM
.detpure eltsihw ehT
.stigid detcetorpnu no nwod swaj lufrewop owt deppans ylkciuq dna kcen sih denarc dah tnenoppo enisru siH
.ygetarts rexob-tuo eht eunitnoc t’ndid eh ,ylnedduS
.hcamots dna taorht s’regit eht ot stih suoicoref owt htiw thgif eht dedne namuh eht ,yllaniF
.daeherof sih evoba depiws swalc s’drapoel eht
.noisserpxe gnignahcnu emas eht htiw dehcaorppa onihr dnuobelcsum ehT
erehw roolf eht no ton
.erofeb sa diulf sa t’nerew swoble siH
.ecaf eht morf elbissop sa raf sa swolb gnikirts daetsni dna ydob reppu s’rettal eht gnidiova remrof eht
.srenniw rehto eht fo eno yreve did oS
.em ta nwod gnirats onihr eht dettops I ,txeN
I…setilaicos namuh fo dlihc tsedle eht rof egnahc citamard a etiuQ
.tuo deppord sniwt hateehc eht nehw rehtruf em derovaf
raeh nac eno gniht gnitfilpu tsom eht
”?ynnart ,yssup em gnillac eno eht er’uoY“
.tnemeerga erusolcsid-non a ngis ot uoy tcepxe I tub
.taorht eht ot yldigir smra nwo ym gnisserp dna kcab sih dnuora mra na tsiwt ot ssim sih gnisu
.gnar eltsihw ehT
,emod noitcurtsnoc eht fo gniliec dnalb
.dworc eht hguorht yaw sih devohs dna dehsup ylhguor neht
.htrae eht ot drawkcab gnillaf
,llat eht sdrawot feilebsid ni pu derats seye yM
.yldloc dias I ”,daed s’haiboT“
.revewoh ,nalp eht htiw emac elcatsbo llams enO !stnioj dna stniop
.kcolc eht nurtuo tsuj t’ndluoc I wenk I
.maercs dezinoga s’namuh eht yb tuo denword saw kcarc elbidua na dna
,hguoht eciffo eht edistuO
,sicoV sumoD yb ”sesiurB noeN“
deltit allevon ecnamor lacirotsih a dehsilbup yltnecer osla eH .noitcif
.margoloh egral a deyalpsid gnir eht evoba gnirevoh enord tahT
,noisiv lennut dah ro erac t’ndid rehtie onihr ehT
.thguoht I ?huh ,remraws A
,uoy no kcehc dnuorgkcab evisnetxe na did nem yM“
flesti edirp dna
.selims lanoisseforp dna sdon fo tseltbus eht gnivig ,dias eh ”,tcerroC“
.paeh suoicsnocnu na otni despalloc enilef wollef eht litnu daeh sih gnihcnup neht
,ezirp gninniw eht mialc ot reh sa regae sa tsuj stnenoppo rehto enin htiw tub
,em hcnup ot nwod denael eh emit hcae em gnilapmi deirt taht etehcam tfihsekam a otni toN