.wap reh yb assiaT gnibbarg ,tuo deppoh dna
",sdneirf ym ssim I-I dna loohcs siht ot gniog deracs m'I tuB"
,ecilA no dednuor rehcaet ehT
".reirret ,yaw ym ni tog uoy ekil skooL"
tsuj ew tub ,derit teg thgim ew dna
,skrow yddad ruoy erehw yrotcaf eht snwo rehtaf yM"
t'ndid I"   ".boj ym esol thgim I dna ,gnihton rof eb lliw ttocyob siht taht yrrow I
.drayloohcs eht sdrawot dekool ehs sa trid eht ni gniggaw regnol on liat reh ,ereht tas ehS
,elzzum gnol sih nwod yaw rieht dehcni dah sessalg siH
?sedarg doog gnitteg ylpmis rof skooB
".evarb ton m'I ?evarB ?huH"
,dnereveR ,uoy raeh I"
,denethgirb ecilA tub
,detfil elzzum s'euqinimoD elihw
rethguad reh fo swap dehcnelc eht morf desae repap fo pils a tub
.taht od reven dluow I"
.spil reh no lworg tfos a
?saw I dna dehsinup eh t'nsaw yhw ,ammoM"
,detpurretni eibboR "!eurt ton s'taht ,hu-
.sgniht recin eht etaicerppa ot woh wonk t'nod tsuj sgod emos hguoht
.ttocyob ruoy ni uoy pleh ot dediced ev'I ,oS .em devom
,swap reh derauqs dna
?yako ,ecnereffid a ekam ot ereh er'uoy taht rebmemer tub"
,rennid gnikooc
,ti ekil ot dnabsuh ym tceps' t'nod I dna
.euqinimoD no dednal ti litnu
.triks reh no gut eltneg a tlef ehs nehw spets owt nekat dah euqinimoD
,segavas er'uoy taht syas rehtaf yM
seillub thgif ot esufer I
.ssalc ot gnitteg eb dluohs ehs taht ngis a sa ti koot tsuj assiaT tub
rood eht denepo euqinimoD
.euqinimoD dna ytteB ot txen dnats ot emac dna ksed sih dnuora morf dereep eh
"-yhtlif uoy ,nos ym no swap ruoy tup llits uoy tuB"
,haey ,I-I" .god wohs a fo
,emit no er'uoy ,ylrae er'uoy fI"
,klim eht gnihctef dna seye nedal-peels gniknilb reliewttoR ykculp a ,sneh eht gnideef namreboD evitunimid a
"?eibboR ,rof taht od uoy
.nuf fo stros lla 'nivah esle enoyreve dna
.daeh reh tsniaga desserp srae elttil reh
,derevihs ehs ,ffo dap rethguad reh dehctaw euqinimoD sA
.reh tsap klaw ot deirt eibboR sa tsuj ,tuo swap reh fo eno kcuts ehs os
"!reirret ,ssenisub ruoy fo enon si sihT
".meht teg attog I ,ybab ,em
.enod ev'uoy tahw wonk reh tel dna
,ti ni dnuora llor ebyam
srae s'reveirter ehT
.sserd reh no elkcub eht htiw gnitegdif
.gnilruc spil reh
s'assiaT "?ew nac ,ammoM esaelP"
.skcart eht ssorca morf m'I esuaceb yltnereffid em gnitaert esle enoyreve dna srehcaet eht fo derit m'I ,llew -tsuj s'ti
!hctefkcuD a fo sdrow eht revo
.esrup reh dnuora hcnelc wap reh tlef dna
.emag a ni erofeb thgin eht rehtorb redlo reh ffo now d'ehs ezirp a
.loohcs taht ot ffo assiaT gnidnes
,skoob ym pord em gnikam ,em devohs
neht dna noitcerid sih ni detrons ehs
denaorg syob htoB   ".seillub ton
:ecno ta deneppah sgniht owT
,pleh s'assiaT tuohtiw dna gab ym koot eH .did eibboR
.mih dniheb god gnuoy rehtona dna ruhtrA htiw ,reilrae morf
,denrut syob ehT   "!ffo kcaB !yeH"
siht ekil gnihtyna od reven dluow
.tih gnieb tuoba desaelp t'nsaw eh tub
,esnopser labrev a eviecer t'ndid euqinimoD   "?uoy truh ohW
retteb yna wonk t'nod uoy dna gnideerb ruoy s'ti wonk I
.stnerap neewteb gnitrad seye sih
.taes sih ni nwod knirhs igroc eht dna kcab spets wef a ekat reveirter eht gnikam trons reh
?elbbip uoy ,gniyllub tuoba wonk uoy dluow tahW"
elkcuhc a derahs
,deppilc erew sdrow reh ,ekops ehs nehw dna
elzzum dehcnelc reh hguorht ylhguor tuo gniwolb ria eht
",krow ot yaw ym no saw I"
,flesreh dnefed ot ecnahc a reh nevig neve t'nevah uoY
enihw tfos a litnu sdrow sih revo gnillum
.rehtom reh nwod derats ehs sa
eibboR "!ti detrats ehs-ehS"
,rae yppolf a detfil assiaT
.detsiser pup eht tub
.ni eveileb ew tahw rof gnithgif era ew
.draug-ffo yletelpmoc assiaT thguac kcab reh fo retnec eht ni evohs ehT
,stnemom esnet wef a roF
redluohs s'eibboR otni hteet reh knas ehS .etib
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sdneirf diputs sih dna eibboR ot pu doots uoy ,naem I .era uoy ,seY"
.troter a tuo deremmats ehs sa ,yruf htiw detrotnoc ecaf reh
,seye reh ni gnimaelg noitanimreted eht
ssergnoC ni sgod ralloc-esool
,wap reh deppat dna
.yrd swap ytniad reh peek ot erac gnikat
.redluohs s'assiaT no ti tup dna
",meht gnitpurretni yledur erofeb gnikaeps hsinif srehto tel sgod dezilivic ew tub ,skcart eht fo edis rehto eht no seussi eldnah sgod uoy woh fo erus ton m'I
,assiaT dnamirper ot elzzum reh denepo ehs ,gninworF
"?llaw eht ni gnidih tar eht dnuof ehs erehw trap eht daer uoy diD"
,niveK yltsenoH" .kcab srae reh desserp ehs sa
,sgod derb-llew dnuora eb ot gniog er'uoy fI
.deneppah tahw tuo dnif ot elddim eht otni deppets rehcaet ecneics eht dna ,gnuws dna stsif sih dehcnelc reveirter eht
,erofeb dias ev'I sa dna ,noisnepsus ruoy tuoba yppah ton m'I"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
evitcepserri ,yrots eritne eht raeh ot tnaw I taht
.ylsuoiverp eibboR ekovorp did dlihc ruoy taht dias taht rekraB .rM morf troper a dah ev'ew elihw
".loohcs taht ot assiaT gnidnes dna boj ym tuoba gniklat erew uoY"
",esaelp ,hctefkcuD .srM"
"!trats a s'ti tub
,reh ekil srehto dna lrig teews siht rof pu gnidnats ,hcum eb ton yam tI
.ngis taht nopu dekool ehs nehw gninetsilg seye reh
kcab denrut ehs erofeb gnineve eht rof edistuo peels meht ekam ot netaerht dna erom ecno syob owt rieht renroc
,yrotasucca secaf rieht
.deppans dna elzzum sih delknirw reveirter eht elihw ,reh ta gnilworg naitamlaD eht
,rettiwT no selaTylriwS@ &
efil efas ,doog a s'tahW
!sreirret tluda nwod gnisahc rof edam t'nerew sgel yppup ybbutS
,uoy rof deracs m'I"
,assiaT ot detniop eibboR
.sevren elttirb ydaerla s'euqinimoD no gnitarg enot eht
,wap a tuo dleh eH
,euqinimoD ta detniop aehtroD
.srae yppolf reh ta gnipsarg swap reh
ot dnetta ot mih rof srettam tnegru gnitic ,drawrof emac
.tirips gnithgif suoegaruoc 'srotsecna rieht rof detargined netfo erew yeht
"-er'uoy ,emit no er'uoy fi dna
repap detanimal fo eceip niht eht barg ot deganam ehs ,swap gnikahs reh etipsed tub
bonk eht gninrut erofeb rood eht tsniaga yltneg gnihctarcs
reh dnuora gnippihw taoc yvaw ,tfos reh
uN"   .gnissim sriah wef a dah ylno
,meht dnim t'ndid assiaT tub ,won meht dnuora gnirehtag dworc a saw erehT
.ti koohs ehs sa gniddon
,dehguoc rettorT lapicnirP ",mehA"
syob suoitcnubmar fo riap a
"!em ekil kool taht sgod emos tsuJ"
".elpoep yrgna wef a fo esuaceb truh teg ot lrig ybab ym tnaw t'nod I dna gniht thgir eht gniod eb ot tnaw tsuj I-
.sdrow sih htiw gnieerga ,sdaeh rieht deddon dna derumrum noitagergnoc eht
"?loohcs retfa uoy eeS"
reirret redlo eht ta seye reh deworran aehtroD   .trela dna
,ylper yrgna eht emac ",oN"
,emoh em gnivird saw dnabsuh ym elihw yad rehto ehT" .dias ytteB
"?gnorw gnihtemos yas I diD" .deirrow dekool
,ecilA htiw pu hctac ot
.loohcs ruo ta erutuf s'yppup ruoy ssucsid ot ecnerefnoc rehcaeT/tneraP a rof uoy ees ot tcepxe ew
.em rof pu doots reve sah ydoboN"
.ngis eht was ehs litnu ,erots ybraen eht otni og dluoc yeht taht gnipoh
",ssarg naht etercnoc erom sah krap nwo ruo dna
,spup rehto eht htiw ti erahs ot detnaw assiaT
,dehgual assiaT .delzzup ylraelc
,hA"   .ti gnitsrub
,taes reh otni nwod dils assiaT
.sredluohs niht s'assiaT dnuora ti gnipparw dna retaews reh ffo gnippirts
:pu gnitteg tsuj spup doohrobhgien rehto eht was ehs ,redluohs reh revo dekool assiaT sA
"-wonk uoy evah ll'I
.ammoM ,tluaf ym t'nsaw tI"
.deppots rac eht sa noos sa tuo trad ot gniraperp ,rood eht ta dewap euqinimoD ".sgniht
"!kcab tekcaj ym tog dna eibboR htiw em depleh taht lrig eht s'tahT
"?raeh uoy ,hcus sa tca lliw uoy
,reh sdrawot dehsur eh sa dworc eht morf psag elbidua na saw erehT
",thguoht yeht tahw ssel erac t'ndluoc I"
.hcum selcihev ni edir ot teg t'ndid euqinimoD
".uoy stius ti sa noos' sklof no skcab ruoy nrut ll'ay
deleenk euqinimoD
daeh reh detlit ecilA
.ecaf s'rethguad reh revo
.worbeye na desiar dna
?gniod uoy era tahW !won yeH"
,pu dekcap ehs elihW
,desuap ehs neht tub ,trapa ecalp eht gniraet ekil tlef euqinimoD ,tnemom a roF
esuaceb ll'ay tsurt ot drah s'ti taht snaem ti syas ehS"
,emit hcus retfA .2
"!ammoM"   #   ".yako s'ammoM ,ybab seY"
.gnitsetorp m'I esuac' uoy taert ll'yeht woh dna
".sgod ssalc-dnoces ekil detaert gnieb fo derit er'eW
.smra s'rehtom reh otni repeed gniworrub ,derepmihw assiaT
rethguad reh dnuora swap reh depparw euqinimoD ".ybab ,ereh emoC"
,ereht doots ehs sA
,yawa ti epiw ot wap ykahs a htiw tuo dehcaer
sredluohs s'assiaT dnuora mra na gnipparw ,deddon euqinimoD
,etal oot ton er'ew epoh I"
.sdrow gnitnuat sih dna reveirter eht no saw sucof reh
.uoy tifeneb yltcerid t'ndid ti fi em ekil sgod nees reven evah dluow uoy ekil sgod
redluohs reh yb assiaT debbarg eH
"!gniniar strats ti erof' no emoc woN
,dnats ot ytiliba eht spup ruo fo lla dna ,spup ruoy dna ,spup ym evig nac I fi taht wonk I
.taorht reh fo kcab eht ta gnitcelloc saw taht elttips eht gniwollaws ,dias euqinimoD
?sub eht gnikat t'nera owt uoy yhw nosaer yna os
oot tsehc reh ssorca smra reh dessorc euqinimoD
dneirf tseb ruoy eb ll'I
,esolc reh dellup ohw
,reh ni tsrow eht tuo gnirb ot yrtogib siht wolla t'ndluow ehs dna
,klawedis eht fo elddim eht ni doots assiaT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.drah ,niaga assiaT evohs ot
.koob a fo segap eht neewteb deirub elzzum reh gnipeek elihw dnuorgyalp eht fo no-sgniog eht ot gninetsil
,depmuj euqinimoD   "!YAWA OG"
daeh sih no tcere srae sih
.reh fo tnorf ni smra reh gnissorc dna
.tsehc elttil reh revo dessorc smra reh htiw redluohs reh revo yldrazahpah gnuls gabkoob reh
.reh fo edisni egrus regna eht gnileef
assiaT ",em ot wen s'tI"
,tuo evig dluow htgnerts reh thguoht ehs nehw tsuJ
ton dna reh gnidnes gniht thgir eht did ew fi gnirednow m'I
.eciov reh derewol dna euqinimoD ta delims ytteB ,oirt eht evobA
",mih ot noitnetta gniyap neeb adluohs uoY"
"?loohcs siht nI ?gnithgiF"
hgual dnerever gnuoy eht gnikam
,repmet dibar a hcus sah ehs fi dna enoyna truh reven senots dna skcits ,llitS"
?tahw rof dna sreveirter dna seldoop ybraen eht fo sesuoh eht ni eparcs dna wob srebmem ylimaf rehto dna ,stnerapdnarg reh ,stnerap reh dehctaw dah ehs ,efil reh llA
swap dehctertstuo s'dneirf reh otni depmuj ecilA tub
.koob kraB ycatS txen eht ssucsid ot ydaer
suniplA ”CK“ sisiriK yb
,ylper t'ndid assiaT nehW    ".retteb
"?'evil ot spup ruo tnaw ew efil eht taht
.devil euqinimoD erehw aera eht sdrawot gnideeps nageb dna raeg otni rac eht tup ehs sa dennirg dna siht fo eton ekat ot demees ytteB
,derevocer eh nehW
,redluohs s'lrig nrobbuts eht ta deppans ehs ,gnilworG
.esrup ym ni ereh thgir ,ris seY"
,od I"   .gniyrd seye reh
.rood eht hguorht gnimoc gnirepmihw draeh ehs litnu
,seldoop erew esehT
.seno dlo eht fo eno s'taht tub
,swap reh no saw assiaT ,hsalf a nI
,deddon euqinimoD nehW
,sdneirf sih ffo deggurhs eibboR sA
.nwod stluda eht hgiew ot nageb ecnelis eht ,swodniw eht no nwod dehsalps niar eht sa tub
yllaer a em dellac eh neht dna
.moor eht otni gniklaw dna
.syawyna ereht reh tnaw t'nod yeht
,taps eh "?DI emos tog uoY"
,owt sih tsap gnihsup
,rehtom reh ta dekool
,deksa ecilA "?evarb siht syawla uoy era woH"
".'nikniht ot em tog taht
.retteb mees flesruoy ekam ot tsuj seilleb ruo no swap ruoy peek rehtar d'uoy tub
.reh dniheb gniggaw liat reh ,dias
daeh reh gnihcuot srae reh
,kcab-ot-kcab tas ecilA dna assiaT
",emit tsrif eht uoy draeh I .ti taeper ot deen t'nod uoY"   "-p a em dellac eH"   "?tahw eH"
deelb yehT ?ruf rieht fo erutxet eht si
,stnerap lla ekil
,srae reh deyalps assiaT
.ydaer dna desiop ydob eliga ,rellams reh
assiaT tnemom eht tub ,reh dnuora erusnu
taht naht edih rehguot a sah rethguad yM
,enim dneps ot woh em llet enoyna tel t'ndluow I esuaceb yenom ruoy dneps ot woh uoy llet ot gniog ton m'I
,erofeb eldoop a htiw rac a ni neddir reven d'ehS
,ruhtrA dna eibboR
.reh dniheb thgiarts liat reh
,ti tuoba kniht I taht won dna
",edis rehtie morf gniklat-revo erom on referp d'I dna morf semoc god eno yna erehw fo
.ecaf reh fo tuo rae yarg ,yppolf a gnihsurb dna seye lezah reh gnillor ,dias
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
eibboR"   .niaga sdrow reh dnuof ehs
,revo reh dekconk ylraen pup tsegnuoy reh erofeb raf levart ot evah t'ndid ehS
.elddim reh dnuora guh kciuq a assiaT gnivig
s'assiaT   ".tnemarepmet dna dnik nwo reh fo sgod htiw gninrael ot demotsucca eb dluow ehs
,rethguad reh nopu emoc egnahc taht ees ot god redlo eht deniap tI
denrut ytteB   ".pup ym htiw taht ekil niar eht otni gniklaw flesym ees tsuj reven dluoc I dna 'nimrotsrednuht s'tI
,ffins doog a ti evig dna revo og ot detnaw ehS
redluohs s'rethguad reh no wap a gnicalp ,dias euqinimoD
,kcab tohs euqinimoD
,llits tub ,oga syad fo elpuoc a reh detlusni ydaerla dah ytteB siht dna
.gniwolf yleerf sraet eht
.smialc sih etufer ot gnihton dah yeht dna
I"   .kaeps ot assiaT rof gnivaw
.spup ruo tuoba em gnillet s'ehs nehw efiw ym ekil tol a dnuos uoY
,gnola reh deggard dna
,euqinimoD ta kool ot
"!eibboR ,kcab ti eviG"   "!yppup diputs ,ahaH"
hguorht llaf ot hguone gib seloh evah skcart eht ssorca dnes yeht taht sesub ehT
eldoop eht fo tnorf ni doots assiaT
,stsif otni swap reh dehcnelcnu dna dehcnelc assiaT
,dneirf reh fo ecaf deirrow eht no dednal yeht nehW
gabkoob knip ,thgirb reh deredluohs reirret erihsdroffatS llams ehT
.flesreh etipsed delims ohw
,tekcaj neloow reh otni smra reh gnivohs
.teerts eht nwod kcab llorts sih nugeb ydaerla dah poc eht tub
wap denimreted tub ykahs a htiw tuo dehcaer dna denihw ecilA
"!nekatsim eb yam ew kniht I
"!sub eht edir annaw I tuB"
?ekaw rieht ni riapsed dna sehsa ylno tfel ohw
?siht egnahc ot I ma ohw tub
"!dnim t'now mom ym erus m'I"   "-I-mU"
,flesreh no repeed ni delruc assiaT "!ti detrats hctefkcuD eibboR
,dnabsuh ym erew uoy thguoht I .dnereveR ,yrros m'I-hu-
"?thgir ,euqinimoD !dlrow llams ,woW"
.noitome htiw llirhs eciov reh ,mih ta dekrab assiaT
,hcum t'nia tI
"!em no tuo tsrub tsuj ti evah ot diarfa os neeb evah dluow I !did I"
#   .yppup a fo diarfa erew ohw
.loohcs eht otni degdurt ehs
.eert kao evissam a fo stoor eht rednu tser ot emac yeht litnu
".eromyna sub eht gnidir ton er'eW !assiaT ',on' dias I"
.gniddon ,ti dezeeuqs dna wap s'assiaT koot ehs ,flesreh gnikahS
,uoy esucxE"
,elitsaC odnalihP ,eciR rimaT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.thgif eht trats t'ndid assiaT"
.reh otni gnirob seye 'setamssalc reh fo erom evah ot evah t'ndid ehs os moorssalc eht fo kcab eht ta detaes eb ot lufetarg
"!elbbip yhtlif uoy-uoy ,em tcepsersid uoy erad woH"
.daeh reh tsniaga ti debbur dna
assiaT ,syad lla fo ,yadot yhW
.redduhs ot spup eht dna rettorT lapicnirP gnisuac
,swap reh no saw euqinimoD ,emit sihT
hguor eb annog s'tI"         #   ?tnereffid
".su naht retteb er'uoy ekil tca llits tub ,skcart eht ssorc' sgod su fo tser eht sa doolb emas eht deelb lla'Y
.reirret eldnirb ,redlo eht ot pu hctac ot deirruh dna
.syaw ruoy htiw krow fo tuo sgod gnikrow-drah ynam os tup ev'ohw snagilooh ydwor esoht fo trap a er'uoY"
.deppans euqinimoD
.esnefed s'assiaT ot emac ehs sa ediw seye reh
.reh ot yretsym a saw keew a syad xis ti etarelot ot deganam semaJ woH
"-tub ti naem t'ndid I-I .mih deppirt I nehw si hcihw
.elzzum sih fo ruf denekciht eht tsniaga wap a gnihsurb
",ot dnetta ot sgniht retteb evah dna namow ysub yrev a m'I
"!evren ehT ?sgod eseht
,hctaw reh ta nwod gnikooL
,dedihc euqinimoD
.htreb ediw a reh evig ot dednet yeht ,yb dessap ehs nehw serutsop deneffits dna srepsihw rieht etipseD
,skeehc reh doolf htmraw eht gnileeF
,deneffits euqinimoD
.reirret redlo eht revo flesmih tressa ot tnaw ot demees dna tuo tsehc sih kcuts eh ,dnik sih lla ekil tub ,kcirederF nos reh sa dlo sa tuoba ,gnuoy demees eH
,siht naht retteb saw ehs
.dias eh tahw fo ecnaifed ni
tsuj I .dnereveR ,uoy knahT"
:dnim reh ot emac taht gniht tsrif eht did dna depley ehS
,evom ot rethguad reh gnitteg saw ehs sa tsuJ
#   .thgilnus retniw elap eht ni
,taht ton s'ti ,oN"
p a em dellac eh-eH"
.euqiN' ,esuac doog a rof lla s'ti ,lleW
".assiaT ,no eunitnoc ,woN"
esucS' .lriG ybaB eb ll'ti
.seippup regral owt eht ta degrahc dna
ytteB dna euqinimoD   "?seidaL
,meht ot gnineppah sgniht wen fo
erehw ,loohcs dlo reh ot kcab tnew assiaT fi retteb eb thgim ti tub
,ti timda ot etah I
s'ylimaf ruoy fo diarfa gnieb fo derit m'I
.yaw taht leef lla ew ,haeY"
.meht ot ti evig uoy tel ot
.lrans a otni detsiwt ecaf sih
sdneirf elzzum-denepo
,desitsahc ylhguoroht neeb dah seitrap lla taht deifsitaS
,wonk reven dluow euqinimoD ,edis nrobbuts reh wohs ot dediced
"!ma I naht flow a gnieb ot resolc er'uoy ekil smeeS .yllub taf
.enihw a htiw evom ot reh gnicrof
,kcab pets a koot aehtroD
,enobmah evissam a no dewang ehs ,wap eerf reh htiW
.flesreh drawrof pets a gnikat htiw gnola
,snialp nepo dna sdraykcots eht morf devomer gnol erew yeht hguohT
,ni deveileb ehs tahw dna
gniroloc hself elap sih
.ylthgil gnikahs ruf etihw ,ylruc reh
sessalg demmir sih revo gnireep
psag eldoop eht draeh assiaT
?'sgniht recin' tahw dnA
dekrims reveirter ehT
.dehsinif t'nsaw ,revewoh ,rehcaet ehT
,meht fo ecin s'tahT"
tsehc reh ot koob reh gnihctulc
,srood eht sdrawot deirrucs spup rehto eht sa gnilffucs dna snaorg erew erehT
,sraey derdnuh owt tsap eht rof swaj rieht nihtiw nwot taht dah sehctefkcuD eht
,naem eb ot gniyrt ton m'I"
.teef reh ffo yppup eht kconk ot denetaerht liat gniggaw ylsuoiruf
.reh fo tnorf ni detaes igroc eht fo elzzum eht no deniart seye neek reh
,sreveirter eht dna seldoop eht erofeb tsuj ton
.euqinimoD hguorht tloj a tnes seye sih ni kool eht tub
reh dniheb digir liat reh
"?yako uoy era ,ammoM"
,ylmlac deksa ytteB
,deffuh hctefkcuD .srM
wap eht debbarg yltneg rehtom reh hcihw ot
,reve sa etalucammi sa saw moor s'assiaT
,uoy no swap rieht tup dluohs eno on tub ,loohcs ni gnithgif eb t'ndluohs uoY"
,dias eibboR ",nac I ,haeY"
,sgod doog eb ot htob uoy gniniart er'eW
".od ot tahw em llet t'nod uoY"
.reh gnipolevne stiucsib tsafkaerb s'gninrom siht fo llems eht
.ecniw reh edam rehcaet ecneics eht fo skrab eht tub
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.loohcs ni sedarg doog teg I esuac' tekram eht ot og ew emit yreve eno em yub apap dna ammom yM
,ecilA ,eldoop eht saw tI .nwod kool dna
semitemos dna ,nerdlihc ruo dna sevlesruo fo tol a gniksa er'ew taht dnatsrednu I
?seitilanosrep dna ecnegilletni rieht etipsed ,gnideerb dna ecnaraeppa rieht no desab degduj yeht erew yhW
,drehpehs ecilop a ees ot dnuora deleehw euqinimoD
.erofeb reh ot ezigolopa eldoop a dah reven d'ehS
'sey' a derepmihw assiaT
,drawrof reh deson dna rethguad reh ta denihw ytteB
,denrut dna depmuj euqinimoD
,pup reirret eht ta
:sevlesruo ksa ot evah ew ,eseht ekil semit gnirud tuB"
”CK“ sisiriK yb ”1203241/weiv/moc.yrrufos.www//:sptth sgoD oN“
dna krow tsuJ"   "?tahw ekiL"
.htiw od ot tsael eht detnaw ylimaf reh dna ehs seno eht erew sehctefkcuD eht ,nwot ni devil taht seilimaf dlo eht gnomA
.meht ta yllacitsaisuhtne gnikrab
,thgif eht detrats t'ndah ehS .gnitliw srae
.haey ,haey hO ?tahW"
,srae ruo ni kcit thgir a neeb sah pup hctefkcuD tahT
.tsiaw reh dnuora euqinimoD hctulc dna pley assiaT gnikam
?sgniht recin eht etaicerppa ot woh wonk yeht t'ndluow yhW"
s'eh wonk I" .esacfeirb sih otni elbib sih gnivohs ,dias semaJ
.ti yned tonnac ew
suoiciv a ekil flesmih gnidarged dna
.koob eht fo srenroc revo-dedlof eht ta gnihcuot
.reh ta gnirats noitagergnoc eritne eht ees ot pu dekool dna
,tnemtaert emas eht tog ydobyreve thguoht I ,tsrif tA
dniheb gniggaw sliat rieht
?taht od ot tnaw uoy erus uoy erA"
,deffuh euqinimoD ",wonk I"
gnirevihs pup reh deciton ehs
.ecivres eht fo tser eht rof decitonnu niamer ot deirt dna elbib reh fo retnec eht ni elzzum reh deirub euqinimoD
ffo gniyrrucs erofeb rehtom reh degguh dna
,ecno liat reh deggaw
.ereh er'ew yhw dnatsrednu t'nod yllaer I"
,ekaw rieht ni demmals rood ehT
.smra sih dedlof dna dehgis eh neht tub
.reh hguorht esruoc regna tlef ehs sa trohs sdrow reh ,dias euqinimoD
?sruoy neve dna gniyllub s'nos ruoy ot pu dnats ot evren ehT"
ti od reven d'yeht
,rehtom reh morf egdun eltneg a htiw tub
!reh s'taht ,moM !moM"
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,tohsrae fo tuo saw eh ecnO
riap eht gnihctac
.moorssalc eht fo edisni eno tsal eht gnieb tuoba rehcaet eht morf piuq a deviecer ehS
".lla retfa eruliaf a saw
"!gnihton od t'ndid I"
.htob meht tidercsid ot
dna ereht tuo sesub doog yltcefreP"
.edisni rethguad reh dna ,krow morf ytteB ,namow eldoop gniyonna eht htiw
eibboR ym dna sih tsniaga drow reh s'ti ,sediseB
,sub aera eht no gnidir sediseB
,erom ecno assiaT ni pu dellew regna ehT
denruter tekcaj reh
.ecaf reh ot nirg a thguorb espalloc gnitluser siH
.pup ,niaga uoy gnillet ton m'I"
,ecnarongi fo ecalp a morf gnikaeps saw I
".'lla-ti-wonk' a uoy sllac rehcaet eht hguoht neve ,ssalc ni srewsna eht lla wonk syawla osla uoy tub
"!flesruoy mlaC !esaelp ,aehtroD"
,gab reh fo psalc eht htiw delbmuf euqinimoD ".esrup
",sessap siht litnu eert siht rednu tiaw ot evah ll'ew os ,allerbmu ym evah t'nod I dnA
sih tsniaga sdrow s'assiaT saw ti ,eurt saw tI
.pot no yats ot sgod lacol eht fo gnimra-gnorts dna ecneulfni
,srehctaC thgiN eht nommus dna ytippu oot demeed eb yeht tsel
reh pleh droL dna rennid 'semaJ gnikooc etal eb dluow ehs
seye s'euqinimoD deredisnoc ytteB
.assiaT ,rethguad ym si sihT .m'seY"
.niaga reh gnihsup ,dehgual eH ".ma
.eiteews ,em ot klat ,assiaT"
,dednuos palcrednuht evissam a
.loohcs ta yadot thgif a ni devlovni saw yppup ruoY   ,tneraP raeD
eninac elgnis a gnilaever
,ekil uoy lla segavas su llac nac uoY"
.enim eb ll'uoy fi
sa tsuj ,sessalom teews fo pollod a htiw aet fo puc a ekil ,gnihtoos dna dlim saw eciov siH .dehgual eH ".spup
,egnahc eht ees ot traeh reh ekorb tsomla ti dna seye s'rethguad reh otni nwod dekool euqinimoD
"!siht fo mih esucca dluow ,rettorT lapicnirP ,uoy taht kniht oT
,llits kcots tas euqinimoD ,reh ediseB
".gnorw saw tnemirepxe eritne siht wenk I
".deneppah tahw yltcaxe uoy llet nac yeht dna
,deddon dnereveR ehT
.tnemtaert retteb rof gniksa dna gnitsetorp lla uoy fo emos was I
.rehtom ruoy htiw tahc a gnivah eb ll'ew
,renroc a ni pu delruc reh dnuof euqinimoD
.srehcaet rieht fo serats gnivorppasid eht etipsed
!dnuohretaW ytteB-B"
",seno dlo eht fo eno s'tahT"
.reh htiw rood eht tuo mih gniknay
"-sgod emos tsuj ,taht ekil er'uoy taht gniyas ton m'I
,koob kraB ycatS tsewen eht tuoba dnuorgkcab eht ni dettahc ecilA dna assiaT elihw meht neewteb delttes teiuq ehT
.evarb os gnieb rof uoy knaht ,oN"
,stneve s'yad eht no gniwets neeb d'ehS
sgniht rof degduj gnieb tuohtiw ,god raluger a sa detcepser eb
,deppans hctefkcuD .srM
.skcart eht ssorca morf god
.sevil rieht fo tcepsa yreve dellortnoc dna suoiciv sa meht yfissalc ot desu saw
"?edir a tnaw uoY
,pils eht dennacs seye reh sa dna
.eelg ni liat reh gaw ot assiaT gnisuac
.rethguad reh yb sthguoht reh fo tuo dekrej ,nwod dekool neht dna
.uoy fo tseb eht teg yllub a tel ot gniog ton m'I tuB
,emoh gnitteg ni etal erew yeht fi tub
"!yddad ym ro em fo ssob eht ton er'uoY"
"-tca ot woh wonk t'nod yeht ekil s'ti taht syas dnabsuh yM
,ohw dneirf reh ta dekool dna
.deklaw yeht rehtraf eht etercnoc ssel dna ssarg erom saw ereht woh deciton ehs ,rehtom reh dewollof ehs sA
".nur evah dluow I !oot eM"
eugnot tfos reh nar euqinimoD sa
"!uoy fo retteb tcepxe dluow I" .gnikrab dna swap sih ot gnidnats
tuo pup eno siht gnilgnis si rethguad ym fi sa mees ti gnikam er'uoY .tluda na sa tub
repap fo teehs eht debbarg euqinimoD
".emit emas eht ta sliat etib dna ffins uoy esuaceb ll'ay tsurt ot drah saw ti dias syawla ammoM
moor eht dellif senihw
,pu derats ehs ,hgis a gnivaeH
,rehto eht ot pup eno morf dekool rehcaet ehT   "!em devas ehS
.epaga elzzum reh
.srae reh otni dellips
,dehgis igroc eht
.skoob rieht nihtiw deirub selzzum rieht fo htob
,reh ta dekool assiaT
".ti ot dnuor' no emac uoy dalg tub
,hctefkcuD aehtroD fo ezag gnirehtiw eht htaenrednu taes reh ni nwod gnireknuh
?nosaer a rof detarapes er'ew taht tpecca sgod uoy t'nac yhW
,reh retfa kcab demrots euqinimoD ,deredliweB .rood eht
,em wonk t'nod yeht esuaceb yltnereffid em taert ot sgod tnaw t'nod I .thgir er'uoY"
fo esnefed ni ,eibboR ekil pup gnidnatspu na tsniaga eil ot rethguad ruoy ecrof dluow uoy taht kniht oT
.ereh taht etarelot t'nod ew tub ,skcart eht ssorca sruoy fo loohcs taht ta wolla yeht tahw wonk t'nod I dna ereh wen er'uoy wonk I ,woN"
.riah ylruc fo pom reh htaenrednu ediw seye reh
,dias euqinimoD "?assiaT"
.daeh reh tsniaga desserp srae reh
,retiB ssiM elttiL ,uoy rof sA
reh ffo dellup gnieb eibboR tlef ehs
,siht yas ot etah d'I
,sserd ruoy no trid eht morf gnigduj dna ,thgif a ni flesruoy evlovni reven dluow uoy taht wonk I ,ecilA lleW"
.em fo retteb eht teg snoiton deviecnocerp ym fo emos tel oot I tub
.wollof ot assiaT dna euqinimoD gnivael
,tsehc sih ssorca smra sih dessorc dna
assiaT ",yadot em rof pu gnidnats rof uoy knahT"   "?ybab ,seY"
".emitemos emoc attog s'ti tub ,retsiS ,ysae t'nia egnahC"
".em dlot uoy tahw meht lleT .ecilA ,no oG
.rethguad ym dellac nos ruoy taht eman a tsuj t'nsaw ti tub ,oN"
,sdnim eht fo gniteem a etatilicaf pleh dluoc I taht dalg m'I"
?dehsinif ev'I taht seno eht fo emos daer ot ekil uoy dluow
"!eldoop kaew ,llamS"   .dedired dna
?niar eht ni gniod uoy era tahw ,yaw eht yB
?ti ekil tlef yeht revenehw dekcik eb oT
dekool rettorT lapicnirP   ".dekovorpnu
llits saw ydob reh hguoht
,detrons dna tsehc reh ssorca smra reh dedlof ecilA
,paos hserf fo tnecs eht
,noitidnoc enitsirp ni syawla era sesub eht taht wonk uoy evah ll'I"
".oot nuf evah ot tnaw I dna ,yppup a tsuj m'I
.ekat ot ysae dna htooms
a gnieb dna dnuora spup rehto gnihsup s'taht god eht er'uoY"
.ereht nworg dah taht retcarahc fo ssendrah niatrec a
esufer I dna lamina na otni uoy ekam ot nosaer yna rof kool ll'yeht
,ylper a tuo remmats dluoc ehs erofeB
,esuolb s'rehtom reh otni elzzum erauqs reh deirub assiaT ".ammoM ,lliw I"
,naelc swap rieht tpek dna krow drah eht ni tup yeht fi
denrut ehs ,gnisuaP
,erom yas ot detnaw ehs fi sa dekool ecilA .meht
.erom ecno gnilworg
,gninrub srae reH
.deniart-lli dna evissergga yrev eb nac sgod uoy fo emos tub
,dias elamef reveirteR nedloG a
deffuh ehs ,sbir eht ni reh dewoble semaJ nehw tub ,gnipytoerets reh dna krow morf eldoop edur taht htiw yllaicepse
,ylneve tuo gnimoc sdrow reh ,dias euqinimoD
.krow ot teg ot ruoh na naht ssel dah ehs taht deciton ehs
.yas ot gnihtemos sah rethguad ym kniht I tub
,thguoht ehs ,meht nmaD
esoht fo tnemirepxe laicos siht spahrep
,assiaT no dednuor eH
.ouq sutats eht gnitpursid fo noitnetni on htiw
,krow ta snoitca reh fo esuaceb eldoop eht fo luftsurtsim tlef llits ehs dna
I"   "?em tih tsuj uoy did ,hctefkcuD treboR"
"?oot dednepsus eh saw ,oS"
.retteb eb ot woh meht wohs tsum enoemos esuaceb syaw lufetah ,ylgu rieht tsiser I
,haey hu dna assiaT m'I"
"!meht fo sdaol tog ev'I
?llew sa desitsahc saw ehs ekil leef ti did yhw tub
gnola swap sih debbur yltnerruc eh hcihw
".deneppah s'tahw ssucsid ot nerdlihc eht wolla nac ew os tis esaelp dluow uoy fi" ,selpmet sih gnibbur won
.stsetorp sub dna krap eht ta gniviecer neeb d'yeht tnemtaert eht edulcni t'ndid taht dna
",revo ti gnikniht retfA"
".tem ydaerla evah slrig ruo gnisseug m'I
"-p a reh dellac eh-eh ,rekraB .rM tuB"
.taoc reh koohs dna ffo lworg eht dekohc
assiaT .tnemevom ylno reh elzzum dezalb reh fo renroc eht nwod gnillor raet elgnis eht
.gninetsilg seye reh fo srenroc eht
.pup siht ylno dna
.reirret a gnieb etah semitemos I-I
?edistuo peels ot meht gnidnes em morf yawa sdnoces evif neve t'nera ohw sucraM ro RJ emas eht naem uoY"
.reh fo tnorf ni derettacs srepap dna skoob reh elihw elit eht no deyalps swap reH
,gnirekcins draeh ehs
,rehtom reh ot resolc gnildduc ,dias assiaT
flesreh rof pu dnats ot woh ammom ruoy dewohs uoY
stnadifnoc dna stnadnetta sih tub
.reh ot txen detaes saw taht llub tip eht ot gnitrad seye reh ,dias ytteB
,ruf nedlog sih htaenrednu
.niaga rebmos werg eh erofeb seye sih ni gniworg thgil eht
"?aehtroD ,evren tahW"
si' ,sevlesruo ksa ot evah eW"
rof gnikool saw reveirter siht tahw yltcaxe saw taht nehw yllaicepse
".ti htrow si tsoc eht fi rednow ew
"-nos ,tsrif yrots eht fo edis reh llet ot gniyrt saw rethguad ym kniht I"
,erofeb siht gniod sih fo foorp yna evah t'nod ew dna ,s'eibboR tsniaga drow reh tsuj si ti tub ,retnuH .srM ,yrros m'I"
,meht ot hguorht teg nac enoyna fI
,erom dnereveR eht htiw kaeps ot detnaw euqinimoD
sa em ekil sgod dewohs ,esruoc fo ycatS sediseb
.yrassecen si ti" ,ylmrif deilper ytteB ",seY"
"?gnithgif tub ,siht naht retteb uoy desiar I dna rehtaf ruoy wonk I won ,assiaT
assiaT ",wonk I ,ammoM seY ".etal-"
.reh decnelis lworg a erofeb deirc assiaT "!hu-
,dehgual dnereveR ehT   ".od ew ekil tsuj
desufer saw ti ,yad reh fo tsom ekil tub
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,suniplA ”CK“ sisiriK yb
.noitneted rof loohcs retfa em teem lliw owt uoy
,niaga lworg ot tnaw reh gnikam elzzum s'aehtroD no kool gums eht
.mih dniheb thgiarts liat sih dna
,seilloc ,seldoop dna ,sretsnom
?reirret a eb ton ot tnaw uoy dluow yhw-yhW"
.gnidliub eht otni deklaw dna
,krap eht nihtiw efil ro sub a no taes a rof
hgis assiaT draeh ecilA
"?su etah yeht od yhW
,dehgis ehs ",thgirla ,thgirlA"
moorssalc s'rehtom ruoy ot og ,treboR"
,skcart eht ssorca pu gniworg morf wenk ehs sdneirf eht fo eno ton dna driew saw ecilA
.redrah reh degguh dna
"?gniyas I saw tahw tuB
,srehto emos naht efil ni tol retteb a nevig neeb ev'I
.assiaT dna euqinimoD ta ylgnirolpmi
I dna hcnub lufrewop a era shctefkcuD ehT
.sdrow sih morf deliocer naitamlaD eht neve dna
"!gniod m'I tahw s'taht os ,seillub ot pu dnats ot em dlot syawla ammom ym dna yllub a gnieb er'uoY"
demees eldoop ehT
,eldoop eht ta derats assiaT
,detaeper assiaT ",ammoM ,seY"
"?gniht thgir eht gniod ew erA
,nees ro daer ev'I gnihtyrevE
,uoy taht kniht oT"
,dias rettorT lapicnirP
.meht ta deppans eciov hsibbons s'reveirter eht sa
rehcaet ecneics ehT
.ma I snaem ti ,enim rof gnikrow yddad ruoy htiW"
,gninihw sih lla rof ,taht mra sih pu gnidloh ,derepmihw
,daeh reh gnitlit
yas ot si taht-s'taht ,t'nod I-I"
,dnalB ardnaS ,yrebrA duamhA
?ruc nrobbuts a eb ot tnaw uoy nehw sneppah tahw eeS"
.retniw gnol a retfa enihsnus fo syar tsrif eht sa thgirb sa dna erup sa
)retal tuoba enihw d'ehs gnihtemos(
"!yad tsrif ruoy rof etal eb annaw t'nod eW .assiaT ,no emoC
.seidal ,llew sa siht fo lla rof yrros m'I"
,gniggaw sliat rieht ,eciffo eht fo tuo deddap seldoop owt ehT
:syad gniwollof eht rof dednepsus neeb sah
.rood rac denepo ylwen eht otni gnitrad erofeb nwod dna pu ecnuob rethguad reh gnihctaw
.esuohtuo eht sdrawot gnirebmul ffitsaM a dna
,rehtom reh morf yawa ekorb ehS
.edis eht ot daeh reh detlit ehs sa drawkcab deppolf rae eno
.riap eht ot gninruter erofeb ,gnizalb seye
efas eb ot spup ruo tnaw ew od
swaj reh htaenrednu morf dekeep gnaf ynit A
"!doohyppup morf gnitrats ,segavas eb tub pleh t'nac dnik ruoy dna uoY
.yltnassecni gnittahc detrats dna denethgirb ehs ,koob reh tuo dellup
.emoh edir eht uoy dereffo I nehw uoy ot ekops I taht yaw eht rof ezigolopa ot detnaw I"
,dias eh ",assiaT tuB
dna krow I ekil krow ot elba eb tsuj ot gnithgif sgod ees ot dna
.sdneirf sih morf selkcuhc erom gnirehtag ,dereens eh
,deddon euqinimoD   "?deracs er'uoY"
,euqinimoD dna assiaT sdrawot eye citehtapmys a denrut igroc ehT
".flesruoy hctaw retteb d'uoy os ,ot detnaw I fi derif mih teg dluoc I dna
.deunitnoc eh
,yawa dekool euqinimoD
.tnemevom yreve htiw gnimaelg ralloc decal-lewej dna
,tcepser eud lla htiw ,rettorT lapicnirP"
,meht ta kcab kool dna
.deworran seye sih
.ecilA ,emas eht rehto hcae taert s'teL
,yawa koob eht gnikrej ,dias
?dnik nwo ruoy htiw eb dna skcart eht ssorca kcab og uoy t'nod yhW"
d'tahW" .derab hteet dna lluks reh tsniaga desserp srae
.reh ta kcab citsalp fo eceip eht gnivohs ,dias eh ",neht no og tseb uoy lleW"
trohs gnihton si srennam tnerrohba hcus fo nos ym esucca dluow ,gnideerb elbatupersid fo dna
#   .meht dniheb dworc a ni gnidnats sgod deredliweb fo wels a gnivael
.dnopser dluoc assiaT erofeb ffo gnidnuob ,deksa ehs
#   .krow ot etal eb ot gnitnaw ton ,sub eht sdrawot ffo deirruh
.sgod sa nwonk gnieb fo yhtrow neve t'nera dnik ruoy dna uoY
,niaga rehcaet ecneics eht saw tI .kcab dehsup dna
.kcab reh ni notab a fo baj prahs eht tlef ehs erofeb ,sgnidliub eciffo eht fo noitcerid eht ni gniklaw nageb ehs ,flesreh gnikahS
,reh dniheb gnilaeuqs assiaT dna
",ammoM ,deracs tog uoy wonk
,rehtom reh ot pu dekool assiaT   "?thgir taht sI"
.ytteB ta kool ot gninrut won
.sgniht ruoy teg ,assiaT
.siht rof yrros m'I"
,dnuora dekool dna sserd s'rehtom reh ta dehctulc pup ehT
.rettam taht rof ,gninrom rehto yna ro
.daeh reh otni emac aedi na litnu sselpleh tlef ehs ,tnemom a rof dna
,riafnu dat a si siht kniht I
,dezeens euqinimoD litnu
,dnopser t'ndid assiaT
.ecaf reh no elims a dna
nos reh wolla dluow gnideerb denifer fo rehtom fo dnik tahw ,srennam dna stnemirepxe laicos fo gnikaeps dna
,nekorb hcnul reh fo ytitcnas eht ,gab reh otni koob reh gnivohS
'slergnom ytippu' tuoba gnirettum elihw
.reh morf edaf ecneconni s'rethguad reh fo segitsev tsal eht hctaw ot deraperp ehs sa yvaeh traeh reh
!rekraB .rM ,gnihtyna od t'ndid ehS"
,gnilggig dna gnihgual ,rehto hcae ot kcab yaw rieht dnuof yeht ,sdneirf tseb owt ekil tub
,teef reh no saw ehs dna ,pu tohs
".ydobyna naht retteb er'uoy gnikniht ,ecalp eht pu gniknits ,ereh uoy tnaw t'nod eW
tub ,em ekil ton er'uoY
.ecitsujni dna gnireffus gnirongi dnuora gnittis peek t'nac I tub
.eciffo eht fo tuo spup eht devaw dna
".sub ytekcir ,dlo na no mucs ekil detaert eb ot naht
,reh ta swap rieht dniheb repsihw sgod rehto eht was ehs
,desiar enips reh gnola ruf eht tpek yliad ecnarongi dna yrtogib rieht htiw gnilaed sa ,retteb eht rof saw tahT
,llew ,hu-tnaem I ,yrros m'I"
"?gnorw s'tahw ,ybaB"
,ereht gnidnats tfel saw euqinimoD
!ylimaf ym dna em ot tnorffa na fo
.aehtroD ot derewoc evah t'ndluohs I ,llew-
.roivaheb tseb ruoy no uoy tnaw I
,loohcs rieht ot gniog eb dluoc ehs taht dehsiw assiaT
"?deneppah esle tahW ?hO"
,mad a yb kcab dleh gnieb retaw ekil ,werg ti
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
eeL ymmoT dna ruhtrA ksa nac uoY
,semitemoS"   "-naht retteb hcum neeb evah dluow sub a gnihctac tub
reirret derb-lli na fo gnikrab eht ekat ot eergidep ruoy
.gniht thgir eht gniod er'ew wonk I tub
,royaM tnatsissA eht gnieb ot tnalp gnikcap elbbik eht gninwo morF
.sreirreT eht ,dnik reh dna ,sgodlluB eht ,seittoR eht rof yaw taht neeb syawla dah tI
,euqinimoD ot gninruter erofeb ffurcs sih fo gnikahs hguoroht a RJ redle eht evig dna snos sih etarapes ot yawa demrots semaJ
!KNOH   ?eurt t'nerew taht sepytoerets no desab detaertsim dna degduj ,reh ekil sgod dna ehs erew yhW
.sgod rehto dna eldoop eht morf yawa yats ot deganam euqinimoD tub ,tsael eht yas ot ,gnitatirri neeb dah krow dna edir rac eht ecnis syad fo elpuoc a neeb dah tI
.tnemredliweb s'dneirf reh ta
,esuohloohcs eht fo tnorf ni deppots yeht sa
.ssalc ot kcab teg ot deen slrig gnuoy owt eseht eveileb od I tub
.meht detpurretni eldoop eht tub
reh gnipolevne allinav dna
assiaT   ".loohcs ni meht thgif ot evah uoy elihw
.rethguad ylbbub dna thgirb yllausu reh morf siht gnitcepxe ton
gniklaw erew ew elihw llah eht ni tsrif reh dehsup osla eH
"-ton s'tI .thgif siht ni sgod on evah uoy tuB"
#   ".stekcop ruoy stceffa yltcerid ti esuac' won su ees uoy woh ynnuF
,meht gnoma lauqe na sa detnuoc eb ot tub
"!ti detrats ehs ,llew hu-
I"   .srae yppolf sih ssot dna
!rac eht potS"   "-tub
,elttab llihpu na ekil mees yam ti dna ,retsis ym ,won drah s'tI
"!em ecaf ot evah lliw yltnereffid syas ohw enoynA
,rehcaet ecneics eht gnitruh fo yaw yb hcum od t'ndid pup reveirter eht fo wolb ehT
.gnihsalf seye nworb sih
.esrup reh dna lanmyh reh rehtag ot
,rehtom reh ediseb riahc eht no tas assiaT
dna lrig eno tsuj s'ehs ,naem I
?keew yreve skoob droffa dluoc yeht taht elpoep eseht erew ohW
.reh fo retteb eht tog gninihw s'assiaT tub
.rettaMseviLkcalB# .lliT ttemmE dna ,renraG cirE
".sniar ti erofeb nur attog ev'eW
"!riah ylruc diputs tog ev'uoy dna ruf evah sgod esuac' god laer a neve ton er'uoY !riah ylruc ,yaw oN"
.esnefed nwo reh ni elzzum reh delknirw dna deliocer ohw
skcart eht ssorca morf god nommoc a
.tnemgdelwonkca ni srae reh fo eno denrut tub wodniw eht tuo gnirats neeb dah ohw
.ti no dnim sih tes eh ecno noissim sih morf derreted eb ton ot
.saw rac eht ecin woh ees ot desirprus saw dna taes regnessap eht otni deppoh euqinimoD ,sgniht reh gnibbarG
hcruhc yemoh ,llams eht ni derehtag dah taht sgod rehto eht ta walc detnulb a gnitniop neeb dah reirret ehT
.esol ylerus dluow ehs erehw
.sgnileef reh ffo gnilttar nageb
.skool ddo reh etipsed
.flesreh no ni knarhs dna
.srehtorb redlo owt reh morf noitaived raelc a
.etagitsevni ot pu tog ehs erofeb
.gnilworg wol htiw decalretni
.saw I ekil era uoy ohw gnieb rof dennuhs gnieb tuohtiw ,dah I naht efil retteb a evah ot uoy tnaw I tub
,loohcs ni sedarg reh fo duorp erew appoP dna ammoM
loddehraD@ aka ,suniplA
,wodniw eht fo tuo daeh reh dah rethguad reH
.nosaer on rof gnippans dna gnilworg ,em ot pu degrahc tsuj ehS"
.pihw a sa trams gnieb dna sedarg doog reh fo esuac' og ot eno eht eb ot assiaT esohc eW
yppup ruoy ,hcus sa dna detarelot eb ton lliw dnik yna fo ecneloiv ,rednimer a sA
,rolyaT annoerB ,dyolF egroeG
"!eh lliw rehtien dna ,siht rof dnats t'now I
.retsnom a ton m'I-m'I
.ffo mih derehsu yeht sa
,level rieht ot nwod reh gnirb dluow sesuohgod nwo rieht ni meht gnithgiF .hgih og dluow
,nerdlihc tsedle owt rieht deye semaJ   ".sucraM ro RJ
.redluohs sih no hctap a ta gnilbbin
,semaJ saw ti gnikniht ,dna reh raen ecneserp a tlef ehs
,thgim ew sa ti thgif dna ,esoprup rehgih a ot dellac lla era eW"
.seilloc dna ,sreveirter
.esneffo eht rof reh pin dluow rehtom reh wenk ehs tub
,srohtua elbidercni ynam htiw seirots trohs dna seigolohtna lareves dehsilbup sah ohw
".taht ekil enoyreve etib sgod dab ylno taht syas amaM
,dias ehs ",melborp on
,nar yeht ,swap s'rehto hcae gnibbarG
"?reh lepxe ot ydaer er'uoy tey
".krow lliw sih fo ttocyob siht kniht I
?gniod uoy era tahW"
,seenk reh ot deppord ehs
,dneirf reh ta dekool dna
.denetfos enot reh sa
snoiton decidujerp emas eht rof gnillaf er'uoy fi sa sdnuos tI
,rellams a gnivohs naitamlaD a dna reveirteR nedloG ybbuhc a was ehs nehw reh hguorht desruoc regna fo hsalf a os
hcamots reh ni ssenkcis elttil a tlef ehS
.elzzum reh no dnal pord a tlef ehs
,gnilretS notlA ,nitraM novyarT
,nezorf saw euqinimoD
".reh ta dehgual dna
.tol a taht teg I"
?tsaf os klaw ot evah mom reh did yhW
.ammoM ,ti fo tsrow eht neve ton s'taht-
,em naht retaerg s'taht gnihtemos tsniaga gnithgif er'eW
"?sah eh ekil god regnuoy a no yllub tsuj ot
"?ygolopa ym tpecca uoy lliW
.siht detrats dna em dehsup ohw eibboR saw tI
.keew yreve no egrulps ot ylimaf reh rof evisnepxe oot raf erew skoob tub
".ecilA s'eman yM .taht rof sknahT
.enil hcae revo decnalg yeht sa gniworran seye sih
,tsud eht ta dekcik dna
dekool esle enoyreve erehw ,stneduts dna srehcaet detirips-naem hcus htiw loohcs a ni reh tup ot evah ammoM d'yhW
spmup reh ni pils t'ndluow ehs taht gniyarp euqinimoD
,delbmum euqinimoD "ris ,seY"
?gnithgiF"         .sdrageR
,seldoop uoy fo lla htiw gniht emas eht s'tI"
".retsiS ,uoy neve dna ,uoy
"?em ot ezigolopa uoy 'niees 'seidal' rehto eht dneffo ti t'noW
gnithgif nees eb reven dluow treboR nos yM"
elzzum eht morf emoc siht ekil gnihtemos raeh reve dluow ehs taht dennuts
,siht naht retteb saw assiaT
,elddup a revo gnippoh
rehgih elttil a liat reh detfil tsuj
,dias rettorT lapicnirP
,em taert ll'yeht woh rof
demmals ehs erehw moor reh drawot gnilerrab
,tnemugra rieht dah srehtom evitcepser rieht retfa syad fo elpuoc txen eht rof rehto hcae dediova dah yehT
,dneirf a saw ehs tub
!ytteB ,siht fo raeh lliw dnabsuh yM"
.rood eht tuo reh wollof ot pup reh rof gninoitom ,doots ehS
fo god a rof elbaronohsid thgirnwod s'ti dna ,sgod fo sepyt eseht no tfos neeb syawla ev'uoY !niveK ,esaelp hO"
"?lrig ,nwot fo edis siht no 'niod uoy tahW"
.kcab gnihtemos gnidloh erew ehs fi sa
.daeh reh pota detfil srae reh
hT"   ".em dna uoy ekil sgod raluger ro sttum ytsurc-reppu er'yeht rehtehw fo sseldrager
dehgis dna worbeye na detfil euqinimoD
,su wonk neve t'nod uoY
.gnizalb seye sih
,thguoht dnoces a tuohtiW
.mih dniheb liat gniggaw eht etipsed ,elims leurc a ni detsiwt saw ecaf siH
deknilb euqinimoD
,ega gnuoy sih etipsed ,mih ot ria lager a dda ot demees ruf etalocohc ,krad siH
.tniop a evorp ot evah ew esuaceB"
,drah saw ecaf s'euqinimoD
.reh fo deksa noitseuq siht gnivah morf dehsaba gnileef
denetfos sloop rebma esoht dna
.ronaemed sih sa daeh sih fo pot no gnidleiynu dna digir sa srae detniop sih
,ecaf s'euqinimoD no denwad elims wols a dna
.rennid etal a tuoba enihw god taht raeh ot dah ehs fi
".niav ni eb ton lliw robal ruo fo lla taht wonk I neht
".oot deracs m'I .pup ,wonk I"
sdneirf owt sih fo tnorf ni thgir thgif ot
!dneirf ym er'uoy ,rehtie retsnom a ton er'uoy tub-
,dias assiaT ",eman ytsan
,ecnanetnuoc suoicanet a dna selcsum denifed htiw sreirreT naciremA dna erihsdroffatS lla rof remonsim a ,ruls ehT
esuaceb gnithgif enodnoc t'nod I
,kcab deppoh dna depley eldoop regnuoy ehT
.reh rof pu gnidnats rof sknaht tub
.tsacnwod seye reh dna daeh reh tsniaga desserp srae reh ,deilper euqinimoD
,niaga em devohs eh dnA"
",hguor elttil a eb thgim yadot taht
".yadot dnim ym no tol a dah I tub ,gninetsil neeb adluohs I dna"
,reh desaet sgod nehw detah ehS
,meht ot hguorht teg ot eno eht eb dluow assiaT dias uoy wonk I"
,weiv s'tnerap a morf siht gniyas tsuj ton m'I dna
,llew ,spup raluger eb tsuj ot gnithgif ,ereht tuo spup gniees dna uoy ot gniklat retfa tub
denepo elzzum s'aehtroD
,yna sa emit a doog sa s'won tcepxe I ,lleW"
.reh fo tnorf ni gnivom dna
,ereht saw lrig eldoop eht ylneddus tub ,ffurcs s'assiaT rof dehcaer
.daeh reh detlit euqinimoD
.kram eht sdrawot sserp ot evah
nrut reh edam dnuos gnilffuns A
.ruf reh ffo retaw eht kcil ot deirt ehs elihw
,rethguad reh edihc ot elzzum reh denepo euqinimoD
".rethguad a ni rof ksa dluoc I naht erom si hcihw
.tsugsid ni gnilknirw elzzum sih fo segde eht
,redluohs s'rehtom reh revo dekool ehs sA
,pu dekool ehs sA
.lleb eht fo gniliaw ekil-noxalk eht ta srae rieht dekrep spup htoB   !!GNIRBBB   "-m'I ,oN"
.did yeht dalg m'I"
"!morf uoy wenk I erehw s'tahT"   "-llew-I"
sffurcs rieht yb syob htob debbarg rehcaet eht
,pu kool assiaT edam sihT
.sdrow sih htiw elpoep evom nac nam eht tub
".tuo emoc ot eno wen eht rof gnitiaw m'I
.uoy ton ,nialpxe ot nerdlihc eht detnaw rettorT lapicnirP tub
.pals a fo noitartsurf dna ytisnetni eht lla htiw reh kcurts sdrow ehT   ".elbbip-
lworg a ffo dekohc euqinimoD   SGOD SUOICIV ON
,reh fo tnorf ni rac llams a ees ot elzzum reh detfil euqinimoD     !KNOH
.wonk t'nod tsuj I tub
gnilggig dna gnihgual ,dnuorg eht ot delbmut yeht dna
.kcab ti nettog evah t'ndluow I
.efiw sih ta derats neht dna
".dias I sgniht eht dias evah ton thguo I dna
.retcarahc rieht tsniaga deerb s'god a gnigduj ro suoiciv eb ot tuo spup gnikam seno eht ton er'ew tub
,ylthgit pup reh degguh dna
,niar teews ,erup eht ni klaw ot retteb s'ti
,redluohs eht yb nos reh debbarg dna detrons ehs erofeb ,yldipar desolc dna
,tca toir eht rethguad reh daer ot ydaer
,reh dniheb morF   "!sevlow tsomla
".evarb os eb dluoc uoy taht wonk t'ndid I"
,tnemom yb tnemoM
.eert eht htaenrednu deldduh assiaT dna reh dettops yeht ecno kaeps ot deppots tsael ta dah yeht
?semaJ ,meht yb no dekcip eb ot pu reh gnittes ew erA
.riap eht ta pu gnikool
.rae na dniheb dehctarcs dna denway ohw
etam reh gnihctaw elihw
,retsemes taht emit tsrif eht rof
?snezitic lluf sa detcepser eb ot ro
"?koob kraB ycatS a taht sI"
".duorp ammoM ruoy ekaM
"?raeh uoy ,ssenisub on htiw ereh dnuora gnirednaw uoy hctac em tel t'noD"
,wap eht yb rethguad reh debbarg euqinimoD
eno ekil demees reirret sihT
stluda yb ylriafnu detaert eb reh tel t'ndluow ammom reh taht dalg saw ehs tub
,koot ylyhs assiaT hcihw
,ekahsdnah mrif a rof wap reh dednetxe dah assiaT   ".enim
.yhctiwt dna ediw seye reh
,egnahc fo diarfa er'yeht esuaceB"
,gninrom siht renroc eht dnuora loohcs eht ot gniog eb t'ndluow ehs taht derusne dah noitanimreted nrobbuts s'rehtom reh tub
".edam era seno wen esuaceb efil ni tol rieht gnisol fo
”sgoD oN“ saw sihT
,gnimoc eb thgim tahw rof
.dnopser t'ndid assiaT
"!elzzum ruoy ni taht tup uoy t'nod ,yoB
,stca dnik ruoy woh si siht fi tub ,spup fo gnilgnim dna noitargetni siht rof lla m'I"
,ti daer dna reh morf yawa ti dehctans eH .reciffo eht ot tuo ti dleh dna
.wot ni ecilA htiw tops gnidaer reh sdrawot kcab gniddap
.mrotsrednuht citsiretcarahc a ni
".kaerb remmus erofeb siht em evag loohcs dlo yM .haey ,mU"
seye eht ni ytteB dekool ehs ,yawa gnimrots erofeB
"-gnihtemos od dluohs I taht derugif I" ,nageb ytteB
".meht fo sekil eht htiw laed uoy woh wonk t'nod I
,wol dna nevarc eb ot dediced yeht nehw esuaceb ti dewollaws ehs tub
"?ereht seloh esoht tup ohw tuB"
,denepo yks eht dna
,meht morf gnimaerts sraet htiw seye lezah demmir-der esoht fo espmilg a thguac ehs nehw tub
.sgod eseht rof noisserpmi doog a ekam ot uoy tnaw I .dooG"
.gnihtyreve no gniwehc er'yeht erofeb etunim a rof enola meht evael t'nac ew taht raews I tub ,ybab yrroS"
,ttocyob siht erofeB"   .delworg dna
.striks s'rehtom reh morf yawa deppets tub drah dewollaws ehs
,rethguad reh ta nwod dekool euqinimoD "?ybab ,yakO
uN"   "-dniheb morf em dehsup eibboR-R nehw ssalc ot og ot 'niyrt tsuj saw I-
,reh ot deneppah dah tahw tuo erugif ot deirt ehs sA
.eldoop derruf-ylruc
.stnemhsilbatse niatrec gniretne morf deerb reh fo sgod dna reh derrab taht sngis eht denoitseuq reven d'ehs ,pup a sA
,reh ta nwod dekool rehtom reh nehw sgel reh neewteb liat reh dekcut rethguad reH   "...assiaT"
.retteb su gnitaert trats yeht litnu sub eht gnidir si eno oN
.ti fo kcis m'I dna ,skeew ynam sa ni uoy htiw laed ot dah ev'I emit dnoces eht si sihT
.meht fo tnorf ni ereht gnidnats ,ytteB dna ecilA ees ot rood eht nepo dehctans euqinimoD   ".assiaT nom'C
:seman rieht yas ot uoy rof ekil dluow ehs ,won rof tub
rood tnorf eht sdrawot rae na dekcilf euqinimoD     !gnirrrB
,tuo elballys tsal eht deggard assiaT "?yyyhW"
.swap reh ta dednal dna
.taorht reh ni gnidliub lrans a tlef ehs
.taoc trohs reh ffo gnitarbiv regna eht
".moorssalc s'mom sih ot mih tnes tsuj yeht"
".seigolopa yM .semaJ
.esir enips reh gnola ruf eht gnileef
.uoy eveileb ot denilcni m'I
.looc os eb dluoc skcart eht ssorca morf t'nsaw taht enoyna ro eldoop a taht wenk reven I ,yas attog ev'I"
".thgir ti ekam ot trap ym od ot tnaw I
,eibboR ,reveirter eht was ehs ,dnuora gninruT
.srae eht neewteb gnihctarcs ,tsehc reh ot daeh elttil eht depsalc dna
”sgoD oN“:yojne esaelP
",ma'am ,gnillac-eman rof deen on s'erehT"
.eman taht fo noitnem eht ta lworg a ffo dekohc euqinimoD
tneps efil a s'ti fi
.ydob elttil reh dekcatta taht setib dna spin eht etipsed ,no dleh dna
.rehtie ,yltnereffid yna uoy taert t'ndluohs I
wonk ot uoy tnaw tsuj I"
koob derae-yppolf eht fo tnorf eht ta dekool assiaT
,ruf tfos s'rehtom reh otni gnilzzun ,denihw assiaT ".ammoM
.reh ot teg ot gninnigeb srepsihw dna gnirats eht
reirret eht gnivael ,edisni meht deggard dna
,meht erofeb rewoc ot evah oT
,yltcaf-fo-rettam ,dias ecilA
su morf ecnereffid ylno esohw sgod morf sparcs rof gniggeb ,gnilevorg
edis eht ot koob reh dessot assiaT
",dluoc I esuac' dna reirret diputs a er'uoy esuaceB"
.tih neeb d'ehs fi sa deliocer ytteB
".ti ecaf dluow I .nur t'ndluow I"
"?oot assiaT ybab ym yhW
,reh ekil sgod dna ,pup reh ,ehs
,edis gnuoy eht no
.skrap dna sesub eht gnittocyob dna steerts eht ni gnitsetorp em ekil sgod dna em evah taht