.skcor esoht worht ot thgir eht evah su fo enoN
.stuohs gnitroppus tub raelc ssel fo surohc a yb dewollof
.degartuo gnitteg enoemos naht
,gnihctiwt liat reh fo pit eht eciton I
,flesti efil ym ,esoprup ym neht
,siht noitnem I sa ,taht eciton I ".stsirw
,stuohs raer eht ta enoemos ",klat reh teL"
,elkcat a rof ni og ot diarfa ton si ohw
gnihtemos morf eb yam yeht kniht I emit siht hguoht
.em ot gniht evitisop a ekil smees tsael ta
.ecnerefed fo wohs a eb ot wonk I tahw ni deyalps era srae reH .reh ksa I
,rorrim eht ni flesym ta kool I tub
,stnematset eht hguorht doG fo drow eht gniwonk ni ,uoy erofeb gnidnats ni ,won dnif I"
,regna fo erutcip tcefrep a si ecaf s'hplaR ,won yB
.anacrA rojaM eht morf drac a no desab si ti
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dworc eht fo ertnec eht fo tuo yaw sih sehsup dna dnuora sleehw eh daetsni tub
deelb dlihc rehtona edam ecno ehs nehw llafretaw a deirc ohw lrig elttil eht ees I
,nem fo redael a ton eb oT
dnuora evom triks reh fo kcab eht sekam ti drah os gnihctiwt liat reh taht tbuod on evah I
,ylevitatnet sdon aicuL
.tcejorp EDK eht ni
"!raciv ,su ot noitanimoba taht eviG"
ylneve syas aicuL ",riS ,esaelP"
,reh erofeb spots eH
,dnik emos fo esnopser rehtruf a rof gnitiaw si yob gnuoy eht tseggus ot smees hcihw ecnelis fo tnemom a retfA
.did eh yaw eht ti gnittup rof era snosaer ralucitrap sih revetahw
.eveileb ton did yeht fi ereh eb ton dluow yehT
",htrib ym deredro hcruhc ehT"
.niaga mih ta kcab kool I sa mlac ecaf ym dna eciov ym htob peek ot yrt dna ,yas I ",hplaR ,oN"
?no sdnah ruoy gnitteg no tnetsisni os mees lla uoy taht noitanimoba tahT"
,kcen daorb reh dnuora sih eh dna
.gniliec eht fo trap ralucitrap a ot nward si noitnetta reh taht dnif ot desirprusnu ma I ,hguoht ,ton dluoc I fi nevE
.noitaerc suoirolg siH otni
.detseretni yldlim gnikool emos
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
.eb ylurt thgim esoprup taht tahw
,riniel tsuj ro
",detlob ti peek tsuj t'nac eW"
.tuo yaw eht no pohs s'rehtaf sih morf nekat
.flesym rof kaeps thgim I taht tseuqer
.tnelis nellaf erom ecno sah niaga hcihw
.secivres ytpme dloh reven ew ,won elpoep erom era erehT
.slworg tnalibis dna taht fo xim a sa psil a hcum os ton si tI
deciton ton dah I ".nugeb
seye gnikirts esoht fo srenroc eht ta ruf trohs eht fo gninekrad eht niatrec etiuq ma I ,niaga thgirpu era srae reh elihw tub
hcihw fo noitnetni eht gnihtemos thguorb dah ohw tub
.sdnah namuh hguorht drow sih su evag doG
,sreh fo eciov lufrewop ylnamuhni taht ni syas ehs
,os od I sa seye ym teem ot gnilliw mees meht fo weF
".deen taht fo esuaceb si
,uoy tsap sklaw dlo raey evif a nehw
.teiuq eb ot mih teg ot gniyrt si nrut ni ohw ,rehtaf sih morf yawa llup ot gniyrt si eH .ton ro
,eseht fo yna fo esu fo dnik yna edam t'nevah eno rof I ,lleW
.emit eht lla elpoep rehto ynam os eb ton lliw ereht taht deirrow dna
,em dael dlihc eht tel oT
bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.eunitnoc dna hgis I
.meht ot tnemirepxe na saw ehS
,citegolopa gnikool emos
,decalpsim ton erew reilrae seirrow ym smrifnoc ti tub ,loot krow s'rehtaf sih htiw ffo gninnur nos a ylpmis niamer lliw ti epoh I
.sehctiwt srae s'aicuL fo eno dna ,ecnaigella fo htao eht gniticer si eh hguoht sa
,evaheb ton seod eh fi taht kniht em sekam meht fo htob morf gniddon nrets eht tub
.seye reh ees tonnac I hguohtla ,ta gnikool si ehs tahw ees em spleh dna detniop si ti tub
.thgis fo enil reh wollof I dna ,ylwols dnuora snrut dna
.ecivres tsrif reh eb lliw ti esuaceb
flesreh stup ehs tub ,uoy morf reh dleihs ot deirt ohw em saw tI
,sgnihcaet ym dengised snamuH
:yojne esaelP   .ratS ehT
,gnirpsffo sih ecnelis ot gniyrt si rehtaf eht erehw dworc eht fo kcab eht hcaer lliw
.noisserpmi siht ecrofnier ot tnaem si
ygolohtna taht ni seirots eht lla ekil dna
",elpoep lla roF" ".elpoep lla rof
",em tel lliw uoy fI"
.seod ydobyna sa hcum sa ffo emit evah I tub
,od ew gnihtyreve dna
,nam fo krow eht eb yam htrib ym elihW
ylbmuh I" ,dewob daeh reh htiw dna
,sselnis era ohw esoht tuoba gniklat ton ma I ,on oS"
,egaugnal fo ssenhsrah hcus gnirb ot sa
,tekcaj sih fo dooh eht rednu noisserpxe sih fo espmilg a hctac ot eganam I
.doG fo stnavres sa lufesu eb thgim dnik reh fi ees dna yrt ot reh deredro dah hcruhC ehT
.tnemetats s'rehtorb sih htiw seerga eh taht erus ssel gnikool
.ereht dnats ew sa dworc eht gninioj elpoep erom wef a eciton I
,niaga kaeps ot tuoba si eh hguoht sa smees ti tnemom a roF
,yas ot dah ehs tahw raeh ot detnaw eh dias ohw yob eht ekil
".ycrem ruoy ta flesym evael llahs I ,enilced uoy fI
,gninekrad erom ecno si seye s'aicuL htaenrednu ruf eht taht eciton dna ,elims I
,hguoht ,tey yawa sruoh owt eb ot desoppus si tahT
sruo ekil egalliv llams a ni gniticxe os etiuq gnihton si ereht esuaceb ereh era yeht ,oN
,kcol eht ni yek eht nrut I
puorg lacov a ylpmis naht erom saw siht dna
,neetneves rebmun drac esac siht nI
.em ngised ton did yeht tuB"
.bom eht ssorca sdaerps hsuh A
".swalc reh fo htgnerts eht wonk ton did ehs esuaceb
eht fo sdnah eht ni
.elpoep os ro ytriht ebyam
teiuq yrev si ti taht
.sreog hcruhc yllaer ton era stnerap siH
.era ew tahw si sihT
.denruter sah elims deppil desolc reh dna
",niatnuom yloh ym ot gnirb I lliw meht nevE"
.gnirps naireiP eht fo peed
:ssensuoires emas eht htiw ,seunitnoc eh dna
,aicuL ot gninetsil morf dah lla yeht snoitome revetahw morf hcum os ton si ti emit sihT
noitcivnoc a htiw siht syas eH ".tfos
.won yb nwod demlac evah ot skool puorg s'hplaR fo tser ehT
.dellif swep eht fo tsom evah ot dnet ew raey a syad owt eht
.eralg sih fo taeh eht htiw erif no em tes ot sepoh eh hguoht sa em ta gnirats dna
.secivres ruo morf lla meht wonk I
dellac eb llahs esuoh ym rof
.tuoba kniht ot esufer I
,tuhs ti dloh ot tsniaga gninael ma I rood eht fo edis rehto eht morf tuohs a eht semoc
.dennalp ton saw em ni hcum os
,sdoof rehto dna niarg fo sepyt ynam ;slamina dna stnalp htob gnivreserp dna gniworg
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
dworc gniworg ylwols eht hguorht daerps dah ecneliS
,uoy esimorp nac I tub ,nesohc saw seiceps yM
.eno ykcul eht ma I taht
.ssendas naht rehto
.god.ecioveht ta
.raeh ot su fo tser eht rof hguone ylduol syas yllanif eh "!dad tub ,oN"
.eliforp sdaeRdooG rieht no dnuof seigolohtna eht ni seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy ,eno siht retfa erom ekil dluow uoy fi ,dnal ot taht rof gnitiaw elihW
meht revo nworht neeb dah desilaer ton dah yeht hcihw noisnet fo teknalb eht eciton ot smees dworc eht
,desopmoc erom hcum ,niaga secaf rieht ees I ,meht neewteb evom seye ym tel I sA
.nekops dah ehs sa
,tseirp rieht ma I
,yadot evah uoy sa hcus noitcurtsed fo sloot gnirb ot nosaer dnif uoy stel dna
,hplaR ,yas uoy ekil ,cilbup ni desu era sbahN erehw secalp diova ylsuoicsnoc ot yrt yam su fo emoS
.eerga ot srehto eht swolla ti tub
noisrev hcet hgih erom
.hguoht ,secivres on era ereht nehw tobor fo dnik emos erew ehs hguoht sa egarots otni tup ton si aicuL
nosrep a morf gnigreme esraoc dna peed os gnihtemos enigami ot drah si ti dna ,nael dna rednels si ydob reH
"?wonk uoy ,skrofhctip rieht no
.ertnec gniniart eht sa fo wenk ylno yllaer ew
scinortcele snoitacinummoc fo eceip ralupop eht revo nwod tekcaj sih fo eveels eht llup ot seirt ylkciuq yrev hplaR
.txen eht ot nosrep eno morf seye ym evom ylwols dna knilb I sa
.nugeb ylurt sah ti erofeb neve
,thgirpu era srae s'aicuL
.ti detsop ohw namow eht ot pu yaw sih gnildis ylyls
.taht tuoba yppah oot eb lliw rehtaf sih kniht ton od I
.deirt I fi em liaf dluow eciov ym taht raef rof ,kaeps ton od I .don dna hgis I
.stsirw ruoy no ro stekcop ruoy ni yrrac uoy fo ynam os smmoc eht ekil
,naem uoy tahw wonk I
,etaruc tnatsissa wen ruo fo esuaceb ylpmis si dworc eht spahreP
knird em tel ohw snamuh si ti dna
.sevlesruo rof ylpmis ecivres dloh dluow ew taht wef os semitemos
eciov a fo lworg reh taht hguone ylduol tsuj dna
,enihcam gnicneuqes a ni seneg rehtegot gnittup yb detcurtsnoc eb thgim yehT
,stroffe sselerit rieht tuohtiw ton dluow hcihw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.flac eht htiw nwod seil ohw noil eht eb ot
smmoc reh htiw erutcip a sekat enO
gnihcaorppa gnihtemos dnif ot gniyrt yletarepsed
rotiart drow eht ees ot
erawtfos ecruos nepo dna eerf gnitaerc ro
nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
,tcepxe I ,sah erutcip ehT
.licnuoc ytic eht erofeb kaeps ot tuoba eb thgim eh hguoht sa gnikool
,tnemom a rof mih no ezag ym kcol I
"?naem uoy od tahW" .epahs taht
.erutpircs eht tliub snamuh yaw eht
feirg hcus uoy sesuac ecnetsixe ym fI
,gnol yrev ton spahrep si elzzum eninoel reH
,ylpmis ,saw esoprup ym ,neht nevE
.esuoh siH ni eb ot thgir nevig doG rieht seveileb ohw enoyna yned tonnac ew ,thgir era uoy esruoc fo dna
.txen emoc ot evah dluow tahw htiw pleh ton dluow taht dna
,hcihw ytilicaf a ni ,dnik nwo ym gnoma pu thguorb saw I .ssenmlac dna
,reduol sworg gnilbmurg ehT ".evah
.od ot edam saw I tahw
won tsixe hcihw stcudorP
,tnorf eht ot dworc eht dnuora yaw sih sekam yllanif eH
tel ot desufer uoy dna sgniht nrael uoy pleh dluoc ehs fi
.tluaf ym yltrap si ti ekil leef I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,gnirepsihw tsomla ,syas ehs
,ereh tsael ta era yeht tub
.nwo ruoy no efil hguorht yaw ruoy dnif ot dah evah uoy fo llA
,senicidem ynam neve
,doof suoiciled yllausu
.elihw elttil a rof ti htiw selddif dna
.revewoh ,esle ydobyreve naht detseretni erom skool remocwen enO
,srepsihw ehs "...wonk I"
,era ew gnihtyrevE
,reduol tahwemos ,syas aicuL
,egami nezarb a hcus evigrof lliw uoy fi ,si esoprup yM
yllacisyhp reh ta teg dna yrt ot hsur a neve ro gnituohs thgirtuo ton dna gnilbmurg ylno si ti taht tub
trap llams on ni elbissop edam saw
.gniunitnoc erofeb elims deppil desolc a htiw em ecaf ot kcab snrut dna
,tenofni lacol eht no secalp gniog pu dedne
"!hcruhc eht ni sfres oN"
,anacrA ni dnuof eb nac ralucitrap ni yrots sihT
”nedraG yM nI saeP oN“ saw sihT
.evah tsum ylraelc I sa yletelpmoc os uoy deliaf evah I erehw sgnihT .reh
,lla retfa ,flesti sciteneg fo tpecnoc ehT
,ti ta kool ot yaw evitisop tsom eht ,spahrep ,toN ".sesucxe
.tnemurtsni siH eb ot tub
,boj evif ot enin a yldrah si siht ,llew dna
.noitaterpretni taht htiw seerga ydobyreve ton taht si won thgir ereh htob era ew nosaer eht taht ,tloj a htiw ,em sdnimer tI
sraey tnecer ni ecnegruser llams a edam sah hcruhc ehT
.don a htiw mrifnoc I
,dnim ym ni gninrael eht detaerc sdnah namuH
,ma I sa nosrep a hcum sa si ehS
;ratla ym nopu detpecca eb llahs secifircas rieht dna sgnireffo-tnrub rieht
,elpicsid a emoceb ot
.gninrom yadnuS a no neve
.srehto eht fo seye eht neewteb niaga rednaw ti tel I erofeb
eruliaf a devorp neeb sah
tsixe dluow hcihw fo enon
.secneirepxe ruoy evah ton od I"
seye reh fo dlog peed ehT ".eveileb
a naht erom on si ssecorp eht tub ,sbmow laicifitra ni nworg dna
gnikooc neewteb emit rieht tilps yeht erehw
yreneerg ylevol fo egalliv a ni ,ylimaf a htiw pu worg ton did I
.selacs dna ruf fo nerdlihc rehto eht htiw deyalp ohw lrig elttil eht ees I dna
.noitcurtsed fo sloot esoht
.tfos yllaer skool ruf ruoY"
,swep eht no eno on tsomla gnivah fo sedaced gniwollof
si yrots s’yadot dna
.pu dewohs puorg tsrif taht nehw ti rof ydaer teg ot gnivirra tsuj erew ew dna
,noitcif ecneics dna msilaer laicos fo stib suoirav gnitirw
,ylirgna gninworf llits si ,revewoh ,rekaeps ehT
deef swen lacol eht rof egalliv ruo srevoc ohw tsilanruoj eht ees I dna
.raen semoc eh sa nwod sehcuorc aicuL
,tnasaelpnu gnihtemos dellems evah yeht ekil skool owt ro enO
.tsap gniklaw neeb tsuj evah ot smees ,ylimaf a ,rehtonA
,meht tuoba deirrow ylrevo ma I spahreP
.ssenippah fo sraet morf ton si
.ecnetsixe rieht fo stifeneb eht paer lla ew tub
,erised a ylno ton em ni dellitsni hcihw gniniart nevig saw I
etam maet ,truh steg hctip eht no ydobyna nehw pleh ot tsrif eht osla si ohw tub
.enod dah doG fo nem eseht krow eht rof neeb ton ti dah
.ot ton em decnivnoc ohw eno eht si ehS
.detanicsaf ylevitisop kool neve elpuoc A
",nis tuohtiw si ohw eh tel ,hO" ".droL
.doolb dna hself nwo ruoy fo seye eht ni nettirw
.nis tuohtiw esoht tuoba gniklat trats ton dluow I"
,elpoep rehto ynam os gnoma yadot tespu erom yna esuac ,tsael ta ,ton lliw yeht taht deveileR
.kcab secnalg dna spots eh nehw
seye reh esolc reh ees I ,yawa nrut I sA
,dnik reh fo syalpsid lanoitome no slaunam eht fo trap taht daer ton dah I fi nevE
nekops t'ndah ohw eno eht ,mih swollof nos s'rehctub ehT
.hguoht ,bulc llabtoof s'nerdlihc eht morf mih wonk I
,edistuo dworc llams a gnilaever ,srood elbuod eht nepo dna
,tsixe I yhw wonk I
.hguoht ,thgir si ehS
.thgir si ehS .bom toN .oN
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.su tfel evah meht fo owt eht taht
.su neewteb rood kao kciht a regnol on si ereht dna
.neeb evah dluoc I spahrep sa rehcaet a doog sa neeb ton evah I ,esilaer ot em depleh sah aicuL
- stnalp lufituaeb dna sbreh fo edutitlum a
,nos sih ot syas rehtaf eht tahw raeh tonnac I ".ti
.mih hsuhs srehto tub ,snigeb hplaR "- tnaw t'nod eW"
”nedraG yM nI saeP oN“
,kcab eht ta esoht rof raeh ot reisae ti sekam hcihw
.seirutnec rof enod evah stseirp dna sknom tahw fo
.drow siH daerps ot
.tsirw sih ot depparts
,mih ediseb gnidnats si rehtorb siH
flesruoy worht ylirassecen dluohs uoy naem t'nseod tahT
.ecaps cilbup a ni snoinipo rieht gniciov
.em ediseb dnats ot pu deklaw ylteiuq sah ehs taht ees ot daeh ym nrut I dna
.pu gnipparw ot resolc gnitteg si edaced a fo tsom tsal eht no gnikrow neeb ev’yeht cipe if ics taht em llet yeht dna ,emit emas eht ta neppah eerht lla semitemoS
,noitnetta ward lliw efil s'enoemos rof llac ot hguone degartuo gnitteg ytriht naht ssel on fo puorg A
,yawa htgnel s'mra tuoba
",ereh gnieb meht morf niag lla ew esuaceb
,niaga sdon aicuL "?guh a evah I naC"
emahs elbirret a eb dluow ti taht gniyas ma I"
.doG gniyalp snamuh morf emac I kniht uoy fo emos wonk I
,eman siH ni evres ot dnuob efil ym
.sesucxe reh raeh annaw I"
.traeh ym ni setingi epoh fo kraps a dna
,sdnaldiM hsilgnE eht ni gnixaler dnuof eb yllausu nac ohw
?gniyas er'uoy tahw taht si" ,syas hplaR
.stsetorp delbmum wef a pots ton did tI
sa taht deerced dah licnuoc hgih ehT
,mra sih sbarg rehtorb siH
evan eht fo tluav detartsulli ylivaeh eht ta pu skool ehS
.reh ta sruls gnituohs ton era yeht dna
.taht uoy llet nac I ,esle erehwemos og I dna eno tog renroc eht nwod pohS !sgniht eseht
,nerdlihc siH pleh ot si esoprup yM
.ecaep dnif meht pleh dna
reyarp fo esuoh a
,hctip a dnuora yaw sih swonk ohw ,yob suoires A
;secivres retsaE dna samtsirhC eht rof ni emoc ,od ynam os tahw od yehT
”nedraG yM nI saeP oN“
,won litnu ,wonk ton did I
,su neewteb ecnelis elbatrofmoc yleritne ton spahrep fo tnemom a retfA
.tnavres siH eb ot tsixe I
,thgil eht ni snetsilg
.noitagergnoc ruO .hguoht ,lufhtiaf lla llits era yehT .etaruc tnatsissa ruoy gnieb em tuoba yppah oot ton era yeht wonk I"
esilaer ot smees tnemetats sih hguorht yaw flah tuoba ohw ,nam teiuq yllamron a ,levoH hplaR
:reyarp fo esuoh ym ni lufyoj meht ekam dna"
.noitagergnoc ruo si sihT
.esualppa dna rethgual otni tpure yeht dna ,detfil dah
,sraey eht revo dna
.hguoht ,ecifircas rieht uoy ekam ot tnaw elpoep esehT"
.noitamalcorp fo dnik taht rof esnopser dedaeh level a
.stuohs meht fo eno
.noitanimoba si ecnetsixe erem ym tahT
,krow siH ni tsissa ot gnikroW
.erew lla eW .esoprup fo deen a tub
deirrow dna deveiler htob erusaem lauqe ni ma I
ylkciuq yrev niaga og stel tub
,noil a fo daeh eht dna ruf eht evah yam I
,reirgna emoceb ylno dluow eH
.mih eb tsum ,seY .kniht I syob s'rehctub eht fo eno
.puorg sih fo tser eht ot tuo ti tniop ot pleh ton dluow ti esuaceb ,yas I
ekil leef tsum ti tahw enigami yldiviv nac I tnemom taht ni dna
yas I ",rood eht kcol ot gniog saw I"
.taorht sih sraelc dna
.segde devrucnwod dna senil krad fo lluf ,der fo sedahs
".meht fo eno yb ta dehcaerp eb ot gniog toN
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
"!reh ksa ot gniog ylno m'I"
tsirw sih ot seye sih morf gnitfihs ecnalg ym seciton eh taht erus ekam I
,mih dnuora smra reh sparw ehs sa dna
.saep no krow s'tseirp a ot sknaht
.gnisselb evig ot hguoht sa smra reh daerps dna
,efil otni em thguorb ohw snamuh emas eht
.skaeps aicuL yaw eht ot desu teg ot gniog reve ma I erus ton m'I .syas ehs
.gnihtemos tuoba niatrecnu esiwrehto ro gnitnuh si ti fi thgim tac a yaw eht
.erutuf sih ni gnidnuorg a eb llew thgim ereht
,tcepxe I ,sah eh taht efink prahs yrev a edih ot gniyrt
,snos s'rehctub eht fo rehto eht ,nam eno tops I
.sbahN eht erew os ,krow s'doG saw noitaerc lla
sah eno noitatcepxe eht morf rehtar tub
.truocerof hcruhc eht fo tuo
,eman eht wonk won I elihw
.wenk ew lla saw ti esuaceb ,ti rof eman rehtona dedeen reven eW
.ti rewsna ot tseb ym yrt lliw ylerus I ,em rof noitseuq a sah nos ruoy fi"
.ereh si redael eht ohw raelc ylriaf eb ot mees seod tI
.neeb evah dluohs I sA