.ytpme yal ecalp eht sa dnuora kool dna ,nepo rood eht
.tniop siht ta liaf ot nageb ecnedifnoc 'semaJ
.ylkaelb deddon yrraH .deirc semaJ
.rab eht dniheb morf kcab gnippets ,dias eH ".ot
...no sresuort ruoy tuohtiw steerts eht klaw ot detnaw uoy woh dias syawla uoy woh
...roirp dah esle gnihtyreve ylgnimees ekil meht nodnaba t'ndid nus eht dna dniw eht sa gnol sa
,rood eht ot kcab gniklaw
"!?od ew lliw tahW !semaJ !dog yM"
"!efil tnegilletni si ereht
.enohp eht hguorht eciov a emaC "?ereht enoyna sI ?olleH" .kcilC
.tuo daeh ll'ew neht
.oot nehctik eht otni deklaw neht yrraH
...tsuj elpoep ...fi sa s'ti ...dnuora gnivird ydobon ,elpoep oN
,teiuq yllufhsab deniamer semaJ
mih gnissik erofeb ,delggig yrraH
.dnabsuh sih dnuora rethgit smra sih gniciv ,deirc yrraH
.mih deppots semaJ tub ,gnihtemos yas ot tuoba saw dna pu depmuj yrraH
...ti hguorht efir dna
,meht rewop dluow slenap ralos eht dna smraf-dniw eht
...dnuora gniklaw ro ,dnuora gnivird ydobon saw ereht tub
.delbmurg eH ".tsafkaerb emos erofeb ton tub
.nehctik eht morf tuo llac yrraH draeh neht semaJ deirc semaJ
.doof eht gnitalpmetnoc ot denruter riap eht erofeb
...enog saw enoyreve
.tsal ta detseggus eH
,elitsoh erew meht fo enoN
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
"?eeffoc fo aet tnaw ay'D"
.derepsihw eH "...dog hO"
,ecaf eht fo der yrrehc llits
.s’dnabsuh sih dloh ot gnivom dnah
,srats eht ta pu dekool dna rehtegot yal yeht ,htaerb fo trohS
sdnah sih ni daeh sih tup yrraH "...lla ta ydobon
.noissap fo thgin rieht ot ssentiw ylno eht noom eht
.delims semaJ .detseggus yrraH
.eeffoc sih gnippis ylsuovren
,tekcop sih ni kcab syek sih gnittup dna
.pu kcots ...erofeb dias uoy tahw si
,setunim ytnewt ro net tuoba retfA .dias tar ehT ".tuo
...wonk ayaddahw ,lleW" delkcuhc yrraH
…kcuf knaht hO" .dellac semaJ
.sdoof eht revo kool ot denruter yehT
,demees tI    ...eno yb eno
,elbatrofmoc a erow yrraH
.pu gnikool ,deksa yrraH "?ti si tahW"
yrc ot nageb semaJ
nwod enohp eht desae semaJ
.yrraH dnuora smra sih tup ylwols semaJ
!naem I tahw s'tahT !onoN"
.erom teg neht dna ti hguorht tae
,smoorb sa llew sa
,dedda semaJ ”!efas evirD"
"!siht lla tae ot elba eb ll'uoy dna em yaw on s'erehT"
.spil eht ot ssik a semaJ gnivig erofeb
.ria remmusdim eht degassam
,sresuort sih didnu ylsuovren eH .don dna
.enola ton m’I ebyam taht esae ta em tup d’ti ,llac a su evig dluoc uoy fi tub
,retaw fo selttob htiw meht llif ot nageb dna sgab repap koot owt ehT
.ti tsniaga dediced eh tub
.meht rof tpecxe ...ytpme saw
,egassem siht raeh nac uoy fI .tsacdaorb ycnegreme na si sihT .noitnettA"
,ni dellor thgilthgin eht dna
eht yb tis s'tel ...nom'C" .niaga
.niaga srettel eht gniciton
?evila er’uoy semaJ ?semaJ"
,don eht denruter ylkeem retto ehT dias eH
!ereht tuo gnihton s'erehT
.edisni gnippets riap eht
.pu denrut enoyna fi ees ot gnitiaw
,doof eht hguorht kool ot gnitrats riap eht
,meht fo sgab ruof gnivah noos
…reisae elttil a hguorht teg d'gniht adnik siht epoh I sa uoy ot etirw retteb d'I thguoht I ,ereh kraM s'tI"
.sraet ni dedolpxe ylraen tar ehT ".kraM
.oidar eht no dehctiws dna wodniw a denepo eH .tlef gnihtyreve
"?ereht tuo suonosiop s'ti fi tahW"
,lluf sdraobpuc dna rezeerf ,egdirf ruo evah ll'ew yllufepoh neht dna ti etamitserevo
.egap ytiniffAruF sih no
.oot erew steerts eht
.gniddew s'yrraH dna sih ta nam tseb eht saw eH .lerriuqs a
.dias yrraH ".siht tuoba ytliug elttil a ...leef llits I"
.yletinifni spahrep ,gnipool erofeb
,delims dna dehsulb retto ehT .dias eH ".yrraH
.ot yenom evig ot tenalp eht no ydobon s'erehT
...dab taht t'nsi ...sgniht gnikat sseug I neht ...ydobon s'ereht taht thgir er'uoy fI"
.oot thgis evarg a saw taht tub
sdnuor sih no namtsop eht was I
.semoh ruoy ni niamer
.deksa eH "?oot spohs rehto eht tuoba tahw ...lleW"
.tseretni fo gnihton gnidnif oot eh
"!htrow s'pohs rehtona enola tel
!yrraH tsirhC hO"
...srac denodnaba eht dna
,edis ruoy yb elpoep thgir eht htiw
,naicisum dna retiusruf a sa emit sih fo hcum sdneps ohw
...gniddew eht ecnis su ot deklat t'nevah yeht ...on ...lleW"
.rehto hcae ta dekool nem owt ehT
.enohp eht nwod dehgual kraM
,ecnelis gnignah a retfA .dias eH ".evivrus
koorbtseW kraM   sruoY
,afos eht no gnittis erofeb ,rebmun eht ni dehcnup dna
,rewop dniw dna ralos ni stnemecnavda eht ot eud yllufknahT
.uoy sdnif rettel siht epoh I
.os did yeht sa gnikooc deen t'ndid tahw gnitae dna
"?esoht ...tuoba tahW"
.skcos ddo raew ot nesohc t’ndah eh dehsiw semaJ taht siht ekil semit a saw tI
.sffins lanoisacco hguorht ,tsal ta
.seye sih deworran semaJ .deksa eH
"?od ew dluohs tahw
peelsa gnillaf erofeb ,srats eht ta pu yldnof dekool eerht eht ,derahs sehsulb htiW
.daeh sih koohs semaJ
enohp eht ot decar semaJ
.bup eht fo rood nepo eht ot kcab dekool yrraH
meht neewteb tuo ti gnirahs
.rehtie oidar eht no ydoboN
,lluks sih hguorht ti evird ot gniyrt dna wollip a gnibbarg ,dekrab yrraH
"?elttil a ffo gniwohs htiw gnorw s'tahw ...su tsuj s'tI"
...dnuora s'ydobon fi ...oS"
.elims a htiw dehsulb retto ehT
,deniamer elims ehT
,lamronba eb ot nageb ylno sgnihT
.deddon ylnmelos yrraH
,yad taht deripxe taht sgniht tuo gnikcip
.pohs eht tsap tsuj
.enohp eht pu gnah ot tnew dna
.ylmrif dias retto ehT ".dellik
.sgab owt gnikat hcae
...llew gniod era uoy epoh I ...uoy
deksa kraM "?seilimaf ruoy gnur owt uoy evaH"
.ekotsgnisaB ni pu devil eH
.ti hguorht dehsup neeb gnivah srettel ytrof tsael ta was dna xobrettel eht ot tnew yrraH nehw
,tsael ta ro ,tnedifnoc erom demees semaJ
".uoy gnivael ton m'I" .dias retto ehT ".yaw gnikcuf oN"
.yranidro eht fo tuo gnihton saw
,niaga enohp eht morf tuO
teiuq ...woh gniton
.ytinrete na ekil tlef tahw rof gnar tI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.dnalgnE ,gnikoW raen nwot llams a ni
…dab os eb ton thgim espylacopa eht spahrep
dedaf thgil eht sa evol edam yehT
"~uoy tog ev’I sa gnol sa ,oot nac I
.yawllah eht otni tuo tnew dna pu tog eh sa demaeb eH
,yrraH .dias tar ehT ".erom
,resolc ecap a koot yrraH .deksa eH "?tahW"
,derepsihw semaJ "...gnihtoN"
.teef sih ot tog tar ehT
.emit fo sdoirep gnol rof peek taht sdoof
,nig fo elttob gnikool-ycnaf a pu kcip dna
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.delworg eH "!semaJ"
...syas ti sa yltcaxe gniod yb trats ll'ew ...llew
.derednop yrraH .deksa semaJ
"?!no gniog s'tahW !tahW"
nrut ot tuoba saw semaJ .derettum eH "...dab
...dlrow elohw eht neve ebyam ...eporuE ...dnalgnE...ytnuoc
,yad hcae rof su rof doof hguone ekat s'tel os ...yakO"
der tnew retto ehT .deksa eH
...mmH" !gnihtyna ...ro ...strevda ro ...sretneserp ro
.gniraeppasid detrats tsuj elpoep ...elpoep tuB"
,mih ta kcab gnikool ,retto na
.elihw gnol a rof klat ot ni elttes owt ehT
"?uoy era ...meht gnibbor ton er'uoy ...er’uoY"
.desaelp yeht sa od ot eerf
...enola nem owt eht
,yltfos delkcuhc yrraH
,dias eciov oidar ehT ".seitirohtua lacol dna ecilop eht morf setadpu ot netsiL .mlac niameR
.rac denodnaba na dna
...haeY" .deddon yrraH
...gnar ti dna... ...gnar tI
?noos eripxe taht sdoof ekat ew dluohS"
"?saedi rehto yna toG"
.lamron eb ot gnimees gnihtyreve
”emoH s’ydoboN“:yojne esaelP
icnioc a tsuj s'ti erus m'I
...ti timda ot tnaw t'ndid semaJ sa hcum sa ...did ydobon tub
,999 gnilaid retfA
nedrag rieht fo egde eht ot deklaw owt ehT
--- .yrraH ot ylpmis dias semaJ ".kcuf ...lleW"
.ecilop eht gnir ot dedeecorp dna enohp eht pu dekcip eH .deracs ssel
,dehgual dna dehsulb tar ehT
,yrrow t'noD" .deddon neht
.dias lerriuqs ehT ".thgirla
...sepoh sih sa dne emas eht tem t'ndah kraM depoh dah eh
.uoy ot hguorht gnihtemos teg ot elba eb thgim eh tsael ta derugif dna
.thgirla s'taht fi uoy ot nwod evird llew sa thgim I ,llew ...thgirlA"
...mmH" .deworran seye ’semaJ .deirc retto ehT
.dennirg retto ehT
...no gniog neeb s’tahw nevig
.egap eht fo mottob eht ta tfel neht saw rebmun siH
,yad rieht esinagro ot detrats dna deb fo tuo tog owt ehT .gnilims
.tuhs llit eht demmals tar ehT
.knarp a sa rood ruo hguorht eseht tup enoemos kniht I"
bup a ot revo klaw ot tnemom a gnikat
"?retal esu ot ti ezeerf ot yawyna ffuts siht fo emos ekat dluohs ew kniht uoy oD"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
...ylpmis evah elpoep eht lla taht em llet ot naem uoY"
.daeh sih dehctarcs semaJ .deksa eH
tuB .taht yas did I ebyam …llew …sey hO“ .daeh
”emoH s’ydoboN“ saw sihT
,meht htiw nwod eil dna emac kraM
.derepsihw eH ".dnuora s'ydobon
gninrom yadsruhT ypeels eno ekowa taR eht semaJ
,ecalp elttil siht tsuj morf doof eht lla tae dluoc ew kniht t'nod I
pu detlob daeh s’retto ehT
.thgirlA" .esuap s'kraM draeh eH .derettum eH "...nam
tsiaw eht dnuora semaJ gnibbarg erofeb
.yawrood eht hguorht tup neeb dah taht srettel eht gnidaer
.nac tahw ekat tsuj dluohs ew kniht I"
knabrevir eht ot ksud mraw eht hguorht deklaw yehT
.yrraH 'nikniht dooG"
...esle gnihtyreve ekil ytpme saw tI
,sretaw gniremmihs eht gnihctaw
.nepo llit eht draeh eh nehw
.elims suovren a dna elkcuhc a htiw dias semaJ "...siht
,semaJ dnuora gel dna mra s'yrraH
...oot tuo enog s'oidaR kcoR cissalC
.derettum eH ".dekaerf ...adnik gnitteg ...m'I"
.tpew eH "!eciov ruoy raeh ot ma I dalg woH !kraM hO"
oot deddon semaJ .dias eH ".nac
,kcurtsbmud doots yrraH
,deddon semaJ .dias retto ehT ".emit
...gnireffus fo sngis on ...ssertsid fo sngis on erew erehT
.deplug dna wollip eht derewol yrraH
,pohs lacol a ot pu deklaw owt ehT   .enola erew yeht
nib eht ot tnew yrraH
s'erehT" .yrc ot tuoba yllacitcarp ,yrraH ecaf ot denrut dna
.resolc gnippets ,ylteiuq dias eH "...raed ...semaJ ...mU"
...od ot tahw ...wonk t'nod I ...dog hO"
,retaw delttob ,slaitnessE" .dias eH ".pu
.dias eH ".tor yeht ecnis ,tsrif selbategev dna stiurf od retteb d'eW"
.niap ronim flesmih esuac neve ot elbanu tub
,repap dna nep a pu kcip ot nwonk yllanoisacco si tub
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”emoH s’ydoboN“
.sgab repap erom tuo koot htob yeht dna
...rab eht dniheb llaw kcab eht no stirips fo selttob lluf wef a erew ereht
,noomyenoh ruo no rebmemer uoy od ...lleW"
.evivrus ot deen ew tahw ekat nac ew
...drow retteb a fo tnaw a rof ,llew ...ro
.tius kcalb deppirts-nip sih htiw
.dnuora reep dna
,tnemeticxe htiw deredduhs semaJ
,revir eht ediseb rehtegot tas owt ehT
,lamron dekool esle gnihtyrevE
.ti emmargorper ot gnitrats erofeb ,dias eH "...oot
"?esuoh ruo otni kaerb ot seirt enoemos fi tahw ...tuB"
...egalliv ehT .did ydoboN
.ylthgils gnilbmert dna der yrev gniog
.ti gninepo dna rood tnorf eht ot gniklaw ,dias retto ehT ".revir
...kniht I tahw s'tahT"
.tnemeticxe gniddub htiw dehctiwt hcihw eno
,tsafkaerb no gnikrow trats ot nehctik eht otni gniog
.moor gnivil eht sdrawot kcab gnilbmuts ,detnap yrraH
erehT .ereht neddih saw gnihtyna fi gniees
,llah eht ni doots semaJ .doof fo lluf
.dellik flesym teg ot gniog ton m'I tub
,ytpme erew spohs eht tub emac namklim ehT
,thgin taht retaL
...syad eseht sdik gnikcuF"
...gnihton ...tsuj ...niap fo
sgnidliub ytpme eht ni gnikat
1 oidaR ni gnilaid erofeb ,nageb eh "-
.deddon semaJ "?deraeppasid
esuoh rieht dah semaJ dna yrraH
,rewop esol t'ndluow nwot eht
sgel rednels sih nwod gnippord meht
.niaga deksa retto ehT "?od ot ew era tahw ...tahw ...dog ym hO"
semaJ ot pu gniklaw erofeb ,sriats eht dnecsed dna
"!dnuora gnah t'now I !thgirlA"
daor eht fo edis eht no depmud ekib a ees dluoc yeht weiv rieht nI
,moor tnorf eht ot dnuora gniklaw dna teef sih ot gnitteg ,deddon yrraH
...wonk uoy ,taht dnatsrednu uoy tuB" .deddon semaJ
rood eht gnikcol tar eht
...eb tsuj tsum tI ...I ...yako s'tI"
,sserder ot gnilbmarcs retto eht dna tar eht
,sruoh wef a retfA
"...lufituaeb er’uoy ...dog yM"
.no kcab tup ot sresuort yna evah t’ndid ohw semaJ rof ylralucitrap melborp a
selbat eht fo spot eht nwod depiw dah renaelc a erehw skram wef a
,evila tfel seno ylno eht er'ew fI"
retaw gnippal dna stekcirc fo sdnuos ehT
.derettu semaJ "!deraeppasid
,yrraH dnabsuh sih ees ot revo dekool eH
.bos ot detrats dna
elims tnagele ,tnedifnoc
llew dna evila si kraM esuaceb ,thgirla s'ti ,lleW"
"?thgir ...eid ll'ew
.dnabsuh sih no seye
,yrraH ot revo dekool semaJ
,ti hguorht gniklaw owt eht
...od ot deen ew tahw kniht I ...thgirlA"
.lufmrah gnieb sa tuo doots taht gnihton ...nib a
...cisum fo dnuos on tub
.sodeeps denrettap eulb thgil dna yerg krad fo riap a ylno ni dalc sriats eht no doots yrraH gnidnif yb dednetxe ylno saw esirprus siH
...ytnuoc eht spahrep
.moor gnivil eht ni tas erew owt eht ,setunim evif tuoba retfA
.etalacse ot nageb yrrow fo level 'semaJ "...no
...teiuq yldaed saw ti
,nirg a ot gninedaorb
,der tnew dna deplug semaJ .deksa eH
."!noos ay ees ll'I" .dias eH
...siht ot desu teg nac I sseug I ...I"
"?no os dna retfa yad eht eripxe taht sgniht ekat neht ...pu meht taE
.nirg a gnitpoda dna
.pu meht rehtag ot gnitrats ,delbmurg yrraH ".knarp
"!esruoc fo sey hO"
...eid ot nageb sepoh 'semaJ
...ereht ydobon
.daor eht fo edis rehto eht no
,esuoh eht edistuo doots erew yrraH dna semaJ
,mih dewollof dna delims semaJ
.daeh sih koohs ylmrif yrev yrraH .dereffo tar ehT ".nwot
,teerts eht pu deklaw yrraH dna semaJ
,elihw a rof ereht doots yehT .ytpme fi
.ffuts ruo lla laets ll'yeht ,ni ton er'ew fi ,lleW" .deggurhs yrraH
.niaga deplug semaJ
...siht od t'nod ew fi
...gnippohs ylppus og ew tseggus I ,neht dnA" .dias eH "...enola
.flesmih ot ti daer dna ti denepo eH
,dneirf tseb sih saw kraM .deplug semaJ
...wodniw eht tuo gnikool ,dias eH "...eb
.derednop semaJ .deksa retto ehT
epoh tniaf emos gnivah tar eht
,derettum tar ehT "...syad
.ot ton nosaer a dnif ot elbanu
"!uoy eb taht tel esaelp sdog ylohnu ho ,esaelP
.meht dniheb rood eht gnikcol
.daeh sih fo kcab eht dehctarcs yrraH ".tceffe
"!taht em evig t'nod hO"
,tcatni eb ot dekool sgnidliub ehT
...nialpmoc ot htuom sih nepo dluow semaJ
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dias eH ".spohs eht tool
.kraM ,em s'ti sey-Y
lufraF lacsaP yb
erow eh trihs lamrof eht fo nottub eht gninesool
.mih refsnart ot rewsna dluow ydobon
.sdnah sih ni daeh sih gnittup ,denaom tar ehT "...od
,steerts eht ot nruter wohemos dluow elpoep niaga rood eht gninepo yb taht
,nepo saw rood ehT
,niaga ti desolc tub
,dedracsid sehtolc
.nwot dnuora tuo tuocs og I elihw meht nepo uoy tuoba woh ...mmH"
.”…dnuora saw ydobon fi ylno …tub-
.sresuort sih pu gnignah dna
?kraM ...M" .ezorf semaJ
.esuoh rieht ot kcab meht gnikat dna
...enola er'ew erus ekam dluohs ew kniht I"
,ti dniheb reep dna
.gnir enohp eht ot gninetsil
...senohpelet eht tsurt t'nod I wonk I ,llew ...esaelp
",ereh kraM s'tI semaJ raeD"
,uoy tuoba onnud I esuaceb ffuts ruo lla laets ll'yeht ,ni er'ew fI
?I dluow yhw ...ton esruoc fO"
.htuomstroP .rM dna .rM ot gnieb fo daetsni ,semaJ ot yltcerid desserdda saw rettel sihT ...eno ...eno revewoh
.deddon ,gnidnuop traeh
...nac I tseb sa pu ecalp eht kcol ll'I" .deddon semaJ
.thgit gnippirg dna
.semaJ ot gninrut erofeb ,daeh sih dehctarcs retto ehT
.niaga yrraH ecaf ot gninrut ,dias tar ehT "...kniht
"!nwod no emoc ot gniog s'eh dna
.reveicer eht no kcab enohp eht gnippord erofeb
...nam a gniyrram tuoba trap eht ...tuo tfel adnik I
,dnah-ni-dnah deklaw owt ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,semaJ dnuora smra sih htiw gnittis ,deifirtep saw yrraH
si yrots s’yadot dna
.daeh sih koohs dna
meht fo tuo sgel sih gnippets dna
sih fo kcab eht gnibbur
rab eht ot deklaw semaJ
.ylrednet rehto hcae gnilzzun riap eht
...noissimsnart oidar etinifed a fo elkcarc a raeh dluoc eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.esaelp dluoc uoy fI
"?hctaw ot dnuora saw ydobon fi
.tceffe lli yna dah t'nevah I dna nehctik eht ni wodniw a denepo I ,ti tbuod I"
...niaga dessik riap eht erofeb ,dias eh