.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
eveirper lufniap ni ecaf reh hctaW
noitacsufbo sselmrof ni deparD
.rekihhctih flowerew
.lennahc ebutuoy sih no
noitapocnys s'erif yb dekciL eltnam eht revo lworP
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
nemul ediw eht hguorht lwarC
nweh won noitcif morf tcaF
ekam lliw cisum ehT
nac uoY .tcejorP budnaF ohcE gnimocpu eht ni retnuH esahC fo eciov eht sa tsac
edisni syawriats dlog eht nepO
eviver dna sgnirts der mraw eht kculP
swollahs peed eht ni ehtaerB
llaw eht hguorht ylhtooms edilG
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
noisuf ni ecneserp depraW
krow eciov dna cisum sih dnif
latcarf eht ni secaf rof hcraeS
eldnac fo thgil yb taolF
elttar htaed s'onaip eht xaoC
rednet wodaem ni yek eht dniF swodahs eht rednu klatS
,”enrutcoN“   yojne esaelP
rednerrus ngief dna egrid eht liaW
”enrutcoN“ saw sihT     eveileb reh
moor eht ni enola dnatS
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,uohsneguuY yb
,tsulrednaw fo flow ,uohsneguuY yb
llats ytinrete leeF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,uohsneguuY yb meop a