,flow etihw ehT“ ”…s’eH .seY“
?enigami uoy nac ,em ot klat neve d’eh erofeb hsid etiruovaf sih mih kooc ot dah I
rettiwt no ffutsyttopS ta
?ereht yllautca erew uoY
.ereht su dedeen uoy yhw ees t’nod I“
,thgir ,edis tfel ym ot elzzum sih gnignirb
”.noitulover eht erofeb evael ot seilimaf elbon eht fo tsal eht gnoma erew sruO
.sesufer ylknalb ehs tub ,rewols ti ekat dna ,erom nwod tis ot reh teg ot deirt ev’I
,naem I ,tuB .ecap nwo ruo ta krow dna ,tnereffid lla er’ew wonk I“ .syas eceeR
.noihsaf fo tuo gniog saw ti fi sa
.em dniheb noitasrevnoc eht no yltnetni sucof I sa ,krep srae ym dna
.syad eseht aitamlaD rof llew gniog eb ot smees ti tub“ ,dias annoN
.ytilauq ekilmaerd a no ekat seye reh dna
nehctik eht otni daeh neht dna
.lamron yletelpmoc tsuj si pihsnoitaler s’eceeR dna luaP fi sa ,taht ekil gnihtemos htiw tuo emoc
,ylevissessop mra reppu sih gnihctulc ,selims annoN
.ylniatrecnu sbmuht ym gnilddiwt ,yas I
”?ykciN ,dias nam swen eht tahw taht t’nsaW“
”.tiaw dluohs ew ebyaM
,em htiw eceeR ekat I os ,tuoba klat ot deen I sgniht emos tog ev’I
.guh kciuq a em sevig dna
,stops eht tuohtiw tub ,naitamlad rehtona ekil skool tsomla eh ,su fo lla gnomA
.snotsip dna sdor emos htiw gnolA“
.oznE elcnU ,rehtaf s’ebaG nisuoc dna
.ylitraeh shgual dna ,syas ehS ”.eurt yreV“
,emas eht lla gnola gnimoc dnim t’nod I yas ot ton s’tahT
losarap a fo edahs eht ni ,nedrag eht fo renroc eno ni nwod tis ew dna
”.dlohesuoh ruo ni tnedicni edialedA eht tuoba klat t’nod eW
”annoN“:yojne esaelP
”,edistuo eht no flow a eb thgim oluaP“
.yltnesba regrub a spilf dna snirg eH ”,ykciN ,xaleR“
,reeb ym tpecca ot spots ,flow eht ,luaP
tsuj uoy fi ylisae ytterp spots yllausu gnikoj fo dnik taht tub ,erus ,hsidlihc fo dnik s’tI
”,wonk dluow eh sseug I os
”?doof laer htiw rettam eht saw revetahw ,dog yb ,eucebraB
.dnabsuh sih sa hcum sa tsomla ,dworc eht tsniaga tuo sdnats eH
.enot citegolopa erom a htiw syas eceeR
,yldneirf dna htrae ot nwod yrev s’eh
”.stops ruoy dna uoy ,heE“ ”.ti
.gnikool t’nsaw annoN elihw top eht morf kcuns d’I lufnoops eht no ekohc I dna ,maerdyad ym fo tuo em spans noitseuq ehT
”?eceeR dneirf ym ot uoy ecudortni reve I did ,annoN“ .stellif nekcihc pu gnippohc trats dna swap ym hsaw I os ,revewoh ,meht fo yna naht esaelp ot reisae raf si zaD elcnU
.tuoba erom derac ehs tahw wonk t’ndid I
.yldessarrabme daeh ym gnihctarcs ,yas I ”,wonk I ,wonk I“
”.esirprus ecin a saw tI“
.eganrac on ees I ,rood adnarev eht hcaer I nehw tub
,egap yrrufos sih no eye na peek ,sgod dettops tuoba seirots erom roF
.thgin taht em htiw decnad neve eH
”.fo duorp tsom ma I yrotsih eht s’tahT
,dennuts ylthgils smees eceeR
.yaw siht ti did ew dalg m’I tuB
.eman ruoy teg t’ndid I
”.raey txen kcul retteb
sevird eH“ .etag eht fo tuo gnilbmuts ,yas I
,noitautis ym sdrawot erew yeht nepo dna gnidnatsrednu woh nialpxe ot sevlesmeht revo gnillaf yllacitcarp erew yehT
.nirg a htiw em ot snrut eh sa gnittab liat
.detarepsaxe ,enevretni I
”.yad eht ni kcab eman tnenimorp a ,ylimaf isamoT eht morf smets ti eveileb I“
.niaga tuo enut I ,no selbma noitasrevnoc eht sA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
”?thgir ,dneirf a rof gnihtyna ,yeH“
,gniciton rof tsuj uoy evol d’eH“ .syas eceeR
.tuo sdnif annoN nehw cisum eht ecaf mih tel ll’I
”.kcart eht otno gnipacse rewopesroh emos tsuj saw taht ,haN“
.reeb sih morf giws a sekat dna
,saw naitamlad rehto eht emosdnah dna gnimrahc woh tuo detniop I nehw tub ,ffuts yrotsih eht otni erom teg ot em eripsni d’ti thguoht eH“
”.sruoy ekil kael t’nseod rac ynapmoc yM“
.derae ytniop dna
”.acsehcnarF ,uoy knahT
,lufhtuom a dniheb morf selbmum luaP
,deman evah t’ndluoc I ,meht fo tsoM
”,lamron s’taht tub ,tib a dnuora ekoj meht fo emoS“
,annoN yM   ffutsyttopS yb
”,tuo taht detniop ydaerla ev’I ,seY“
”,ti tup ot yaw eno s’tahT“
.ylimaf ym dnatshtiw nac luaP erus ekam ot tsuj
.emit eht ta revird xirP dnarG noipmahc dlrow eht htiw ytrap a dednetta ecno I ,yrtnuoc dlo eht ni kcab ,wonk uoY“
.sriahc citsalp dlo owt no
.tsael ta snoisacco tsom no ton ,lleW“
,em ot revo secnalg eceeR ”.etanoissap yreV
.mih gnitcartsid era nehctik eht morf stnecs eht taht llet nac I tub
.og ot ti tnaw t’nod I erehwemos og nac ti erofeb noitasrevnoc eht gnigrevid ,syas eceeR
”?reh htiw siht tuoba klat
.redluohs ym gnittap ,syas eceeR
?wonk uoy t’nod ,lrig gnuoy a tsuj saw I
?gnikooc lanoitidart emos fo ecnahc a …nmad naem I
.ecaep ni spup ruo esiar dluoc I dna rehtafdnarg s’ykciN erehw
.t’ndah I fi mih ot uoy ecudortni ot erus ekam d’I derugif I ,syawynA“
.htiw spup evah ot lrig emos gnidnif em tuoba hcum oot deirrow ehs thguoht I
,ereht thgir rewsna na mih evig t’nac I
,llew gniog era sgnihT .selims eH
”.flesruoy rof spup tog uoy nehw uoy llet ot gniog saw I“ .deksa annoN
.yoj tsethgils eht revo od ot dnet sliat ’sgod dlo yaw taht ni
.ssalg a evah ,raed ,eceeR“
.gnimrahc os reve saw eH
”.taht ssenisub ydoolb a hcuS“
.yadot gnimoc s’eH“ ,ksa I
.evots tneicna reh no ecaps eht fo tsom pu gnikat si
yb enod tuoba tsuj eb dluohs eh ,fo gnikaepS“
.tsirw ym skcams ehs ,gninthgil sa kciuq tub ,nap eht morf slesrom gnilzzis eht fo eno kaens ot yrt I sa ,ylper I
.nehctik eht otni mih sllup dna
”.taht no pu uoy ekat tsuj thgim I“ .selims eceeR
s’taht ,ereht revO
”?neht ,deirram uoy era
”.yad eno nwo ruo fo ,spup ro ,sbuc teg ot gninnalp era I dna luaP“
.ykciN ,uoy fo dnof s’ehs ekil sdnuoS
,ti ot desu s’eh sseug I
.tib a gnineffits elims reh ,syas ehS ”,hO“
seman suoirav eht tuoba srebmemer ehs hcihw sliated lanosrep tuo stniop ehs ,neht dna won yrevE
ylkciuq kcilf srae siH
,retrats seires racrepus 8V ,lautca nA
,mih ta skniw dna strons ebaG
,syas ehS ”,lufrednoW“
.doof eht ot noitnetta rieht nrut noos stseug ehT
,elzzum sih no pu gnipahs krims gib a htiw revo gninael
derugif I os ,oot aitamlaD morf si ylimaf siH
.tuo eb ot wonk ew esle enoyna ro ,mih ro ,su fo rehtie fo dias drow dab a toN“ .stroper eH
”?eman tsal a evah eceeR siht seoD“
”,ykciN ,inam el ittavaL“
”,thgir tuoba sdnuos taht-T“
.etag eht hguorht semoc flow etihw a ,neht tsuJ
,enim naht srae sih dnuora deretsulc ylesned erom era stops siH
.nehctik eht morf esnopser eht semoc ”?eceeR ti sI“
.meht sraeh ehs kniht t’nod I
.elims gniwonk a htiw eniw reh spis ehs sa
”.od I sa gnol sa evil sannoN ynam toN
.elims ediw a htiw naitamlad trohs a ,mih dniheB
.railimaf dna efas leef gnittes eritne eht gnikam si
,eceeR ot txen riahc a pu sllup dna sdon luaP
.eerga ot denilcni m’I
”.daeh ym fo pot eht ffo llacer t’nac I
.tsap eht ni rehtegot nehctik eht ni tneps ev’ew semit eht lla ot kcab em sekat sllems fo xim ydaeh ehT
.redluohs s’luaP dniheb dworc eht ta gnirreep ,mih sksa eceeR
.s’eceeR ot elzzum ym hcuot I ,hguoht ,gnikniht tuohtiW
.erew yeht thguoht I ohw yltcaxe ton era ylimaf ym
,muludnep a ekil ylwols gniggaw liat reh
”.aciremA ni seilimaf tnargime rehto eht tuoba tol a em llet nac eh erus m’I“ .sedulcnoc ehS
”?yako ,tib a rof nus eht fo tuo teg s’teL“
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,eulb dna kcalb ,rialcniS rof
”.nwo ym no saw I fi nees evah t’ndluow ylbaborp I sgniht ees em depleh uoY
no stops teg ot gniog er’uoy ,yawevird s’annoN s’tI“
.eceeR ,sevlow eht ,sretsis dna srehtorb ruo rof drager tsehgih eht dah syawla ev’I“
.noitasrevnoc eht ni nrut neddus eht yb draug ffo thguac ,remmats I
”?uoy t’nod ,ti rof pu sekam doof eht kniht I“
tsuj dluohs uoy spahreP
”.uoy teem ot ecin ,ebaG m’I“
”,dnoces a rof taht tuoba kniht ot evah I“
”annoN“ saw sihT.annoN dnif ot
”?he ,rac ynapmoc ruoy sa kciuq sa tsomlA
elims ytliug a em sevig eceeR
dluohs I leef llits I tub
.neht dna won yreve ni kool semitemos I“
,siht erofeb reh dlot evah d’uoy fi kniht I
?slrig itteraillI eht fo eno htiw emac eh ebyam ,hO
.syad eseht krowrepap tsuj s’tI“
eceeR ”,raed ykciN ,kniht d’uoy naht drawrof thgiarts eroM“
”.eno ees I nehw nameltneg emosdnah a ezingocer t’nod I taht dnilb dna dlo os ton m’I
.revird rac gnicar eniuneg a si luaP
.esuoh eht sdrawot mih llup I sa ,eceeR llet I
.ffuts enildoolb dna egatireh taht tuoba erac llits ohw tenalp eht no tfel bulc taraccab ruoy dna uoy ylno s’ti erus m’I
,yltnesba ssalg eniw ytpme ylraen reh gnilriws llits ,dias ehS
,ti fo wonk ot smialc eh elttil tahw ro ,eert ylimaf sih otni sevled eceeR sA
.noitaripsni fo dnik taht deen t’ndid I dediced eh ylneddus neht
”.wolb eht noihsuc ot ,eman ylimaf dlo eht dah uoy taht depleh ti kniht I
.skool egnahcxe neve ro ,gnihtyna snoitnem ydoboN
,teerts eht pu gnimoc enigne rac a fo lrans eht raeh nac I tuB
.elbuort sih rof elzzum sih no kcil a flesmih snrae dna
.eciov reh sreyal edirp fo gnits A
,gnitcepxe t’nsaw I hcihw
”.luaP dna eceeR ot olleh yas ,ydobyrevE
”?syug rehto eht htiw og ti
.ydaerla sraey rof sdneirf neeb ev’yeht fi sa
nwonk ylno saw eH
,seigolopa ,he …uoy knahT“
,detcepxe evah d’I tahw ton s’tI
.nehctik eht retne I sa
”?ykciN ,thgir taht t’nsi
.yllaer hcum os derettam taht kniht t’nod I“
.oot ,yug ecin yllaer a eb ot sneppah osla eh ,ffo lla ti pot oT
did woH“  .elzzum sih dnuora ti emos gniraew sa llew sa
”!ereh revO .raed ,luaP .won
…esoR si siht esac hcihw nI
”?rac sih no wobniar elttil ytterp eht htiW .rebmemer ,kcab syad wef a ,noisivelet eht morf eno ehT“ .em sksa ehS
”,acsecnarF ,dnik yrev s’tahT“
eniw elbat doog eht fo ssalg a mih gniruop hguorht yawflah si dna ,riahc nehctik a ot mih sediug ehS
?ti t’nsi ,eniw rof ylrae s’ti ,annoN“
,mih rof das yrev saw tI
”.zaD ,raeG poT hcum oot dehctaw ev’uoY“
,mih dnuora esabnaf elttil eht morf eerf skaerb dna su ot snrut luaP
spup dexim dna dettops fo gnirettams A
.tey taeh dna nus eht ot demotsucca nworg ton s’eH
.noos neppah ot gniog s’taht taht ,gnihtyreve dna reerac s’luaP htiw ,kniht t’nod I tuB“
”.edam saw yrotsih …hu …eht nehW
.melborp a eb ll’taht kniht t’nod I os
”.adrevaL id acsecnarF annoD s’tI ,raed ,nodrap ,hO“ ”.eman
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
sdon eh tub ,dnoces a flah rof senilcni sworbeye s’eceeR
.flesreh ot selims annoN
”.ti gniod fo yaw tuoba-dnuor a saw siht kniht llits I“
.deneppah gnihton fi sa top eht gnirrits seunitnoc ehS
”.siht retfa otni em gard ot gniog si flow eht enituor tuokrow eht daerd ylno I .yawa em peek ot yrT
,gnikooc reh fo stnecs hcir eht ni ekat I sA
”.wonk uoy enoemos gnignirb s’eh kniht t’nod  …I“
”,no s’eh revenehw secar eht hctaw yeht dna ,rennid yadnus rof revo semoc yllausu oiraD elcnu s’ykciN“  ”.sey ,galf edirp …eht htiw 8 rebmun rac
.eno tsal eht saw ehs spahrep ro
”.doog lla s’tI .ffuts seiceps ssorc ot ,ffuts xes emas ot gnixim morf ,sgniht fo tol a tuoba looc er’eW
”?rac s’ykciN ot txen dekrap namsetatS ruoy s’ti esoppus t’nod I“ .wap sih sekahs dna ,sdnopser luaP ”,ebaG ,sreehC“
,taht tuoba emahS
.ti fo kniht ot emoc ,llacer t’nod I ,hO“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
erutseg ,pu teg I .t’nod I os
.sgnirehtag ylimaf ni noitargime eht tuoba gniraeh rebmemer I“
”.su nioj dna nwod tis
”!siht em dlot reven uoY“ ”.eiraed ,annoN em llaC“
,ùgar eht ot txen ylgnigdurgeb meht gnikcats ,smeti eucebrab suoirav eht sa llew sa ,edam annoN doof eht lla htiw elbat eht tes eW
.tsenif reh ta aitamlaD .tsuahxe strops a dna ,mac dauq
.gniteerg naitamlaD lanoitidart a rof nwod mih sllup ehs sa edisa wap dehctertstuo sih gnihsurb ,stpurretni annoN ”,em dlot ykciN ,era uoy ohw wonk I ,wonk I“ ”…ot desaelp ,nosmohT
.reh fo dnof yrev ma I dna naitamlad lanoitidart ,nrobbuts ,dlo nA
”.elbissop yletinifed s’ti tub ,citarcuaerub yrev ylbaborp s’tI
”,eb ll’yeht ,slived elttil ykcuL
”.thgif ot dniheb deniamer elcnu sih kniht I“
,rac elcsum dlo s’ebaG nisuoc ym naht eton reprahs a
,rehtom gnissuf a ekil naelc htuom sih sepiw eceeR
,ykciN ,uoy ekil yeht dnA .meht ot klat
”.thgirla ,enim s’ehs ,haeY“
”.suoiruc os reve m’I
”,etam ,ay rof yzarc og lliw annoN“ .niaga tfel neht
.em rof emit dah reven rehtaf yM“
”,yako s’ti ,on ,oN“ ”.em eiraed ,hO
.brubus siht ni ecalp fo tuo hcum yrev dna
.ecin sa tsuj nekat d’ehs
”…spup evah ot elbanu …wonk uoy
.ecnatsid elddim eht otni tuo skool annoN
.yrutnec tsrif-ytnewt eht ni ailartsuA s’tI
.egatireh rieht tuoba emit gnol a rof klat rehtomdnarg ym dna dneirf yM
”.tsael ta ,tneced tca ot yrT“ .naorg I
?thgir ,VT eht no edud yag emos was uoy revenehw pu ti thguorb tsuj evah dluoc uoy
?kniht uoy t’nod ,srehto eht nioj dluohs eW
”.saesrevo gniyduts htob er’yeht taht rehtaf rieht morf draeh I
,elihw trohs a rof dnuora kcits ot evah I tub ,tuo mih pleh ot tnaw I
.syalpsid nisuoc lacinyc esiwrehto ym gniyobnaf gnissarrabme eht htiw llew slaed dna
.tuoba emoh etirw ot gnihton si egattoc elbmuh siht tub ,dnik er’uoY“
,mih htiw eugra ot derehtob eb t’nac I
.krims a htiw stnuocer eceeR
.ydaer tuoba tsuj si doof eht kniht I“
.regnuoy sraey ythgie saw ehs fi sa ,selggig ehS
.stnerap wen sih teem ot tuo dellevart I
,ti dnuora gnitteg on s’ereht tuB
.em ot tauqs denoitnem reven s’eh esuaceb
.yppah yleniuneg os reh nees ton ev’I ,yltsenoH“ ,yas I
”.ti deen uoy ekil kool uoY
,annoN htiw erahs I esuoh elttil eht edisni dnuora mih wohs I
”,etam ,ayartS‘ ot kcab emocleW“
”?ot evah uoy od ,zaD
.eno evah t’ndluoc tub ,buc a detnaw ohw sevlow fo elpuoc gnimrahc yrev A
”.egatireh sih tuoba ’buc‘ wen rieht hcaet ot esimorp meht edam I
.oot tsew rehtruf ylbaborp dna ,tsaoc tsae eht no snaitamlad eht lla swonk ehS
,ereh efil doog a dnuof ew dna ,taht retfa ailartsuA ot emac eW“
.wonk uoy ,ozzalap a ni evil ot desu I
,etatiseh I ”,spup teg
.sseug I strepxe eht ot klat taht evael retteB
.revewoh ,ereh tuo gnilggurts eb ot smees eceeR
.yllacisyhp neve ,detapicitna tsrif d’I sa hcum os tuo dnats t’nseod eh tub
.syawyna elzzum ym epacse sdrow eht tub
,annoN a tnaw uoy fI“
mih dnif ro moc tod yrrufos tod
”,detcepxe naht retteb tnew taht ,lleW“
,gnihtyreve dna ,stops kcalB
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
eceeR si eman yM .iH ,he
.noitpoda rof pu mih reffo ot dah dna semit drah no llef yeht tub ,raey tsal pup a dah nhoJ elcnu s’ykciN
,gniyaws pots liat ym leef nac I
.eceeR ,wonk uoY“ .syas annoN
”?oot ,emityad no redaer swen taht dna ,wonk uoy ,yag s’eH
,rethgual dna esion eht tub
”.yaD ’sgniK yppah dna ,emocleW“
,ykciN ,selur nwo ym ekam ot hguone dlo m’I“
.wap ym fo kcab eht gnibbur ,yas I ”,etiuq ton ,oN“
.taht ekil loohcs dlo tsuj s’ehS
.ti evah dluoc I wonk I
.flow llat eht dnuora rehtag ylkciuq ohw ,snaitamlad fo puorg eht ta evaw I
.nehctik elttil reh ni syad reh fo tsom sdneps ,hcrairtam otcaf ed s’ylimaf ruo
raeh I“ ?lla retfa ,laed gib a s’ti skniht ohw eno ylno eht m’I spahreP
,elbaegdelwonk ylgnisirprus si eceeR
”?erofeb mih tuoba draeh d’uoy spahrep
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ylegas gniddon ,syas ehS ”,eurt yreV“
.revo emac eh nehw flesym htiw od ot tahw wonk t’ndid I
”.meht fo emaceb tahw suoiruc neeb ev’I dna ,emit ym erofeb yrtnuoc dlo eht fo tuo devom lla yehT
”,keew tsal mih tuoba yratnemucod a no tup luaP ,fo gnikaepS“
.elttil saw I nehw ssalc stfarc dna stra ni reh edam I taht gnihctits neerg dna der eht htiw norpa etihw ,derettaps-otamot ,dlo eht gniraew ,segreme annoN
”.oot ,uoy ot dnetxe ll’taht eveileb I dna
.etnaloV atamlaD lI sa
.niaga redluohs s’luaP gnippals
”,syad eseht spup esiar ot dewolla era syob uoy
,aciremA morf ereh devom tsuj s’eH“
.duol tuo srednop ehs ”?eceeR …eceeR“
.hcnarb taht htiw tcatnoc dah reven ev’I“
.acsecnarF ,ereh tog ev’uoy emoh lufrednow a s’tI“
,oS“ .ti dnuora secaps knalb eht llif klat rieht elihw sevael yab
”,etag eht hguorht tsuj ,draykcab eht nI“
.noitasrevnoc eht ni llul a s’ereht nehw ,yas I
.elims a htiw mih llet I
,htwertS“ ”.etam ,noitacided s’taht
.ti tuoba kciuq eb tub ,evil I erehw wonk uoy
.sseug I ,si ehs ohw fo trap tsuj s’tahT
.yllaicepse dray kcab eht ekil I
.ylkciuq stsujda eh
.yletilop eniw sih spis dna
,ytrap brubus retuo na otni tsrifdaeh yob hcir siht gniworht
.yllaer ,lufetah s’ti fo enoN“
,ylimaf sih tuoba em llet nac eh epoh I“
.dneirfyob etihw dna kcalb sih ot tnemilpmoc ecin a si
.ylduorp tsehc sih gnippals ,syas ebaG
”.thgir eb ll’ehs ,kcik a ti evig tsuJ“
…kniht I ,ydniC …htiw gnola leirbaG nisuoc ym s’taht dna ,anirI efiw sih dna ,oiD ,nisuoc s’annoN
”.eucebrab eht rof stib dna sraeps nekcihc emos detnaw oiraD elcnu ruoY“
”.wonk uoy ,sgniht eseht em sllet ydoboN
”.thgie tniop ruoF“
.dworc eht ot meht gnicudortni nigeb dna ,dray kcab egral eht otni meht ediug I
,esuoh eht hguorht llac I
,knarc-enalp-talf a htiw noitcejni cinortcelE“
.wohemos tuo pleh
!taht ta kooL“ .smialcxe ehS ”!sey ,hA“
.em ot revo mih gnidnah erofeb
”…doof siht rof t’nsaw ti fI
,su fo lla naht rellat daeh a s’eh ,eruS
.mih ta seye ym llor I
”,noitulover eht tuoba gniklat rehtafdnarg ym llacer ot mees I“
.nworb era sruo lla erehw kcalb er’yeht dna
.rof depoh evah dluoc I naht retteb
hcihw ,em ta detcerid kniw gniwonk a htiw ,syas
.esolc srood rac eht raeh I sa noos sa
.ffuts enildoolb taht lla tuoba hcum oot deirrow ehs thguoht syawla I“
.ynapmoc s’elcnu ym fo wolb eht nepmad ot ,oot ,stseug ruo rof wef a dna ,mih rof reeb a barg ot ykse eht yb gniws I
”.tisiv ot elba eb thgim ew yad eno spahreP
?ehs t’nseod ,eniN no swohs gninedrag esoht sehctaw annoN ruoY
ecnef eht ssorca krab I
.enevretni nac I erofeb
.rehtegot erahs yeht tahw ees I nehw gnignol fo gnits a gnileef tub pleh t’nac I
.noitnetta eht lla gnibrosba luaP htiw
.eucebrab eht yb revo ,nyltaC dna niloC ,spup sih dna zaD elcnu s’tahT“
.nevo eht ni nrut rieht rof gnitiaw
.erofeb siht enod yna gnivah ton terger I
bulc taraccab eht morf edualC dna anavI
,em rof tiaw ot meht rof
,yldednahffo syas eH ”,gniht eruS“
,eud s’ti erehw tiderc tub
,thgiled htiw selims ehs
.tsaeb a ekil skcik ,sraer eht hguorht sttawolik ytfif-ruoF“
”.tib a ni tuo emoc ll’I ,owt uoy no og ,hO“
”,yrassecen neve t’nsaw taht ,haN“
.daeh reh sekahs dna shgis ehS
.eno elttil eht fo tseb eht rof saw ti deveileb I tub
”?thgir I ma ,srevird gnicaR
,ailataN efiw sih dna onnoJ elcnu yM
,eucebrab gnikoms eht ,ytreporp deggar ylthgils ehT
.VT eht no syug yag emos tuoba klat ot meht teg ot deganam I
dna tnecca ytic ,tfos sih etipsed ,taht flesym dnimer ot evah I
.rac gnidnuos evisnepxe na s’tI
.erom yna segairram degnarra od t’nod eW
.pu ti ekam ot ,yad eno rennid su kooc nac uoy erus m’I“
.yas ot dab gnihtyna dah meht fo enon
.dnim reven ,yllautca
,yramesor fo stnecs eht no gnisucof dna top eht gnirrits
.daeh sih fo kcab eht sehctarcs dna
.em rof retaw eht tset syug uoy gnivah detulovnoc mees thgim tI .wonk I won tuB
,deirrow yllaitini saw I  .eniuneg s’eh taht
,ynapmoc sih fo noitingocer ni ,sehtolc depirts yna gniraew ton s’eH
,tib a uoy tuoba deklat eW
…tsuj saw onnoJ thguoht I“ .mialcxe I
,elims reh gniniatniam ,syas ehS
.revo htob meht evaw I dna ,em sees eh nehw pu skrep eH
,noitasrevnoc doog fo muh dnuorgkcab eht dna
.rehtie ,ti tuoba yhs ton s’eh dna ,ylsuoires yrev ffuts taht sekat eH
.flesmih spots eh sa
,annoN“ seog taht eno ehT .tnemmoc dlo eht etaretier ot esolc siht m’I
.ssalc laer fo dnuos eht s’taht
”?revird gnicar ehT“ ”…ehT .wonk uoy
.thgif a ro tnemugra gnituohs a htiw dne t’ndid taht noitautis a rof snalp ycnegnitnoc yna edam ton d’I .tcelfed I
.ssarg nworb ,yrd eht no dnuora gniyalp
.redluohs eht no luaP spals dna ,tuo sllac ebaG
.feiler fo hgis a tuo ekohc ot eganam I dna ,enot tnasaelp emas eht ni seunitnoc ehS
.ti ni toof ym kcits nac I erofeb noitasrevnoc eucebrab xe sued a nevig m’I dna ,dray kcab eht morf tuo seirc elcnu ym ,ylnedduS
,yletaidemmi sdnopser eH
.trap taht snialpxe eceeR fi tseb s’ti ,hcum oot laever ot tnaw t’nod I
”.enim fo dneirf doog a s’eH
,aitamlaD alla ùgar suomaf reh htiw dellif ,top nori tsac ,egral A
”?neht tuo gnimoc eb ll’uoy kniht uoy od nehw ,oS
.smialcxe eceeR ”!yas t’nod uoY“
redluohs reh revo sllac ehS
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”?ew did ,tnemtaert aidem lluf eht meht evaG“
”.ereht tuo wef a etiuq s’ereht ekil sdnuos tI
.rehtie mih rehtob t’nseod ynapmoc duol eht dna
.gnisaet fo egde eht no gniredrob tsuj si leef I
.ylsseldrow ekat I hcihw ,riahc a ta serutseg ehS
?samohT tsuj saw ti spahrep ro nosmohT ro nosamohT rehtie s’tI
.ykciN ,tcepxe ot em dael uoy sa dab sa flah ton si ylimaf ruoY
ffutsyttopS toD V elbuoD V elbuoD V elbuoD  hsalS drawroF hsalS drawroF noloC eruceS locotorP refsnarT txetrepyH si hcihw
”.sey ,stnerap eb dluoc I dna luaP ,krowrepap thgir eht htiW“
”.wonk uoy ,erus artxe ekam ot detnaw I tub ,sseug I“
.ydal evitavresnoc dlo emos tuoba yrrow ot dah I thguoht I ,em dlot uoy tahw morF“
,I“ ”.yas yeht sa ,laed laer eht era uoy
.redluohs s’dnabsuh sih ssorca wap a gnittup
”.taht ekil rac a nwo ot tun tfel a evig d’I
.meht tuoba nettogrof evah ot smees annoN sa ,evots eht no snap dna stop eht rits dna pu teg I .snoitnem eceeR
”.emit eht lla tihs klat syuG .syug er’yehT“
,eceeR ot snialpxe ehS
”.ebaG ,gnihtemos ro draobdrac fo eceip a nwod dluohs uoY“
.revelc dna emosdnah os saw eH
,woN .oot naitamlad a sedir eh tub ,aitamlaD morf rac a evird eh seod ylno toN
I nehW .haey ,hA“
,redluohs s’ebaG sehcnup luaP
.deedni ,deerb egnarts a era yehT“
.syug eht dnuora nwo sih dloh nac luaP taht ees ot deveiler m’I
,ùgar htiw dellif etalp repap a gniyrrac s’eH
,rrup taht ot netsiL
.tuo eugnot sih gnikcits ,mih stpurretni eceeR
ti no ogol maet sih htiw trihs-t olop kcalb eht dna
.emonortem a ekil yawa gnilttar si dna ,tey tcaf taht otno thguac t’nsah traeh ym tub ,em edulcni ot tnaem t’nsi yllufknaht tnemmoc ehT
.evah lliw sruoy ekil ,eno rehtona dah I dehsiw semitemos I
,selbammalf ot semoc ti nehw ysmulc yllausu s’eH
”!ynapmoc emos uoy thguorb I ,annoN“
.ti tuoba klat ot tnaw ot gniog s’eh esruoc fo dna ,nwo yeht rac ycnaf fo dnik tahw dna ,si dneirfyob sih ohw ,detivni ev’I ohw swonk ydaerla eH
,ffutsyttopS yb ”annoN“
,aciremA ni efil tluda sih fo tsom tneps ohw ,ytirbelec ronim a roF
.ti fo erus leef I
.yob elttil ym ot deneppah tahw rednow I ,semitemoS“
,syug eht lla fo tnorf ni ereht thgir ,esolc dnabsuh sih gnizeeuqs
”?yako ,tib a rof eceeR worrob annog m’I ,luaP“
”?uoy llet ton eh did ,hO“
.ti rof ksa reven ll’ehs tub ,semitemos pleh em tel ll’ehS
.seye gniremmihs htiw ecnatsid elddim eht otni tuo gnirats llits
,tcnitsni kcap gnortS
nworgrevo ylbaredisnoc
.ylneddus syas ehS
.eceipretsam ’nikcuf a s’ti ,ay ’nillet m’I ,etam ,enigne na tsuj naht erom s’tI
,enot deticxe na ni tuo sllac zaD
.emit emas eht ta tnedifnoc dna liarf htob
.esolc yrev ti depporc dna ,ruf sih fo erac laiceps artxe nekat s’eh tub
,egaruoC luaP si dnabsuh ym ,yllautca ,seY“
.yas ot yako s’taht fi ,syad eseht neve
.emit drah a uoy evig ll’yeht kniht t’nod I
,dlrow elttil nwo ym otni yawa tfird I ,klat rieht ot netsil I sA
,retnuoc nehctik eht no eil daerb fo sepyt tnereffid lareveS
.won rof ti tuoba hcum oot kniht ot ton yrt I tub
.woble sih htiw luaP gnigdun ,shgual ebaG
,gnikooc tuoba wonk I gnihtyreve em thguat s’ehS
,sessalgnus rengised sih dniheb seye eulb peed eht morf llet nac I dna ,suoigatnoc yllufwa si hcihw elims elbaima ,ediw siht tog s’eH
,inilletrot edamemoh fo top dna ,daerb fo sevaol
.gnihtyreve dna ti no galf edirp elttil a sah rac gnicar siH .oreh lacol a
.su fo emos naht citoirtap erom s’eh tuB“
.annoN yb decitonnu seog ti taht hguone yltbus tsuj
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”?he ,ytreporp siht no tops rehtona s’tahW“
”.modgnik eht ni lrig tseippah eht neeb evah tsum I ,hO
.syart dna stop eht tuo yrrac ew sa snrettap railimaf lareves eciton I ,nedrag eht nI
”,eceeR siht teem ot tiaw t’nac I ,lleW“
,wap dlo ,ykahs a htiw ssalg reh slriws dna shgual ehS ”!moor fo stoL
.setad ym no htrow s’ti lla rof lliks taht desu ev’I dna
”.detcaer ehs woh was uoy tuB
,dworc eht fo kcab eht ot ylthgils dehsup neeb sah eceeR
?aciremA morf mih htiw enoemos gnirb eh diD“
sredluohs gnippals dna gnihgual
,syas ylneddus zaD
”.os kniht I ,haey ,he ,I“
.ees ot si ereht elttil tahw eceeR nwohs ev’I retfa
”,lufrednow s’tahT“
”.emit fo tol a ekat spup dna ,eeb ysub a hcus s’eH
.reeb fo elttob sih morf giws a sekat dna syas eceeR
,ffutsyttopS yb
.sbrubus eht ni tuo ,ereh gnoleb seod eh ,sehtolc ecin
.em htiw ereh si eceeR taht lufknaht llits m’I tuB
.thgir uoy taert lliw yehT
.noitasrevnoc eht ni gninepo na si ereht nehw ksa I ”?annoN“
tsuj ot ekil s’ti tahw rednow I
.eceeR ,em nodrap tsum uoY“ .em sksa ehS