.tnelis deyats dna dehgis eh tub
kcapkcab eht edistuo saw eh taht woN
,gab eht fo eerf daeh sih tpek leafaR
.namecilop a saw eh tuo dnuof yeht nehw noitcaer taht dah elpoep fo tol A
.yot a ekil dekool ti esoom eht fo klub eht ot derapmoc tub
.edisni ti tup dna taoc ruoy piznU
.ti yduts ot nageb dna
.yawa nellaf dah seert eht ,niaga degreme eh nehW
,flesmih degguh leafaR
noitciF degnaF yb dehsilbup seires seidoB gnignahC eht etorw ohw
,skooB goD wobniaR dehsilbup
.mih dnif ot setunim neetfif tuoba evah uoy os ,noos strats ecar ehT"
.revihs tneloiv ylralucitrap a yb dekcarw saw eh sa yawa dekool leafaR ".hsubma
.dilos gnizeerf meht fo raef rof pu kcab srae sih krep erad t'ndid eH
.eert a dniheb dekcud tsrif ehs ,pots did ehs nehw dna
ot resolc esoom eht thguorb dna wons fo sduolc pu tnes sevooh s'tnaig eht fo gnidnuop hcaE
.sroloc fo ynohpmys a ekil ria eht hguorht gnibbob dna gnikcilorf
".gab eht ni teg ,woN"
.ecar eht strats eh erofeb dneirf ym ot klat ot deen yllaer I ,si gnihT .ti hctaW !norbaC"
".strats eh erofeb kcul mih hsiw ot detnaw tsuJ
.pu kcab ti deppiz eh sa gnirevihs ,taoc sih otni kcab otohp eht dekcut leafaR
.eltsoj elbaeganam a ot nwod dewols gnicnuob ehT
.noil gniraor eht ,oeL gnilaever ,detfihs weiv sih dna renroc a denrut eaM .retteS hsilgnE na sa tra lacigolohtym ni detciped yllausU
,dworc eht hguorht yaw sih ekam ot deunitnoc leafaR
,liat delruc sih deggaw leafaR ".ma'am ,sknahT"
,deb sih desuffid thgil tfoS
.ecap reh dewols ehs hguohtla gninnur deunitnoc eaM ".won
.ereh pu dedne I woh aedi on evah I dna ,yppup a ton m'I"
.nepo deppord elzzum s'leafaR
.esirprus ni deknilb dna deppots leafaR ".era ew ereH"
.eye s'esoom eht fo etihw eht ta yltcerid lerrab eht nwod dethgis
.regnif a htiw decart dna pam reh no tniop a debbats ehs ",noitatS antneY
taht htmraw eht dna taht rof lufetarg
.etal oot eb dluow ti neht dna ,gninnur dna ffo saw puorg s'ieW gnaW erofeb setunim erom wef a dah ylno eH
.railimafnu saw yks eht nevE
.gnileer mih tnes taht ogitrev gnidnuop a htiw miws daeh s'leafaR edam tnemevom neddus ehT
.srae desopxe sih otni tib ezeerb dloc a dna
.epat eht rednu dekcud dna ,nezorf flah ydaerla
.noisiv sih ssorca enil der a denrub ti taht
"?eman ruoy s'tahW"
"?trats ot tiaw srecar eht erehw wonk uoY
.aera gnitiaw bac ixat eht sdrawot sngis eht gniwollof nageb dna delwocs leafaR .ybbol tropria eht fo htmraw eht morf spets eerht ylno saw eh dna ,dloc ydaerla saw eH
3 traP # .peels ot ffo detfird eh dna
.suoregnad sa meht fo thguoht reven d'eh tub
,dednuop daeh sih fo kcab ehT 2 traP
.taoc retniw knip mug-elbbub sih fo ralloc eht pu dellup dna derevihs leafaR
.ylteiuq deffuhc leafaR "...woW"
yrots s’yadoT dna
"!kcab em ekat t'nac uoy ,oN"
.moolrieh ylimaf a s’ti ,sknahT"
.diov derevoc-wons a ni gnola decnuob leafaR ekil leef ti gnikam
.tnatropmi oot saw noissim sih tub
kcapkcab eht otni nwod kcab ylluferac mih tes ehS ".ereH"
.mih ta dekrab ssob sih "?uoy era erehW"
.gninepeed eciov sih ni lworg eht
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
.reduol deirc leafaR ",su gnisahc deppots esoom ehT"
.taoc sih fo kcab eht yb pu mih dekcip dna wap a htiw gab eht otni dehcaer lrig yksuh eht sa depley eH "!yeH
.deppart elihw kcab reh guh ot tseb sih gniod
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.flesmih ot yltfos detaeper eh "?esooM"
.yug elttil ,retteb nevE"
.sdworc eht tuoba thgir neeb dah eibbac eht tuB
,deeps pu dekcip ehs dna daeh reh tsniaga talf kcab tnew srae reH .delworg eaM ".sseug
tsomla ria dloc eht leef dluoc eh
.em gniddik eb ot tog ev'uoY"
.si enim fo dneirf A .yldrah ton ,aH"
,duolc tfos a ni dednepsus tlef eH
.swap sih htiw ecaf sih derevoc dna nug eht deppord leafaR "!thgirb ,hcuO"
,eaM tsniaga desserp t'nsaw elzzum sih fo pit eht erehW
,htaerb peed a koot leafaR
.ffo denrut enohp sih
.srecar rehto eht gninoitseuq dna egaggul revo gnibmilc
ni serots retniw fo daed eht ni neve tub ,eciohc tsrif sih neeb t'ndah roloc ehT
.dniw eht fo tsrow eht dna mih neewteb klub reh gninoitisop
;mih htaenrednu yb dehsur dnuorg ehT
,dias god eht ",tekcaj eciN"
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.eloh dehcnic eht rof mih evoba dnuora leef ot dah eh dna ,dedaf dah thgil ehT
,hguorht elzzum sih dekop leafaR
.thgin eht morf tuo dednuos yab gnillol A
,pop a dna hsalf a htiw nug eht morf dedolpxe eralf ehT
,stnamrofni laitnedifnoc ym fo eno s'eH"
.redluohs reh revo dias eaM
.wons ni derevoc lla
.ydob elttil sih deflugne yllatot smra reH
.nid eht revo draeh eb ot gnilley
"?oS" .reh ffo detaidar
,llet ot drah ti edam esion detum ehT
.yltnatsni ezorf taht maets fo emulp a ni tuo deffuh htaerb s'tsaeb ehT
!sgod ynam os erew ereht tub
gnihcaorppa tsaf saw nooN
.hguorht uoy tel ll'I
.sgab sih dna god eht dnuora deldis dna
'.ni kcehC recaR' daer
.decamirg dna mih ta pu decnalg ehS
.rorrim weiv-raer eht ni mih ta gninnirg
.yks eht fo weiv sih gnikcolb
.tsurt nac I ohw wonk t'nod I" .deplug eH ".nemecilop
.hcum nwod ti worran t'nseod tahT"
.ydaets ti peek ot troffe na ni ti dnuora swap htob gnipparw
,eloh dehcnic eht ta dewalc dna dekrab leafaR "!pleH !pleH"
,esle gnihtyna tuo teg dluoc leafaR erofeB "?tahW"
.rewot deppot-galf a ees dluoc eh
.srae denrutpu sih hguorht deltsihw dniw eht sa ti detterger yletaidemmi tub
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.hcnic eht rof gnikool ,yldnilb dnuora gnipsarg dna eerf saw wap devolg sih retal tnemom a dna
,tah sih dnuof eh litnu gnihtolc reh ni dnuora gud eh ,kcab reh no gnola decnuob eh elihW
.stnap ikahk niht sih hguorht thgir gnittuc saw dniw ehT
.daeh sih fo kcab eht dehcuot ehs sa yhtapmys ni gnissih ,wap a pu dleh yksuh ehT
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
,meht fo serutcip nees d'eH
.tsehc reh ssorca smra reh dessorc dna deffuh lrig yksuh ehT ".sdrawretfa
.hgual eniuneg a tuo tel leafaR siht tA
.ris ,ffo emit lanosrep emos gnikat m'I"
.gab eht ni kcab mih wots dna pu mih tfil eaM tel eH "!uoy knahT"
deggurhs leafaR ".ysub
peels ot mih gnillul kcapkcab eht fo gniyaws eltneg ehT
.mih detfil dna pirg reh denesool eaM
.reh fo tnorf ni wons eht ni nwod dna pu gnipmuj ,detsetorp leafaR
htaerb gniffup fo stes owt raeh dluoc eh ,savnac kciht eht fo tuo erew srae sih taht woN
nwod daeh sih dekcut leafaR
",ti fo derit teg reven I
"?rotitepmoc a er'uoy em llet t'nod ,tahW"
.mih dna eaM revo derewot hcihw esoom citnagig a delaever nretnal s'eaM morf thgil gnibbob ehT .palf pot eht edisa dehsup dna eloh eht tuo kcab daeh sih deppop leafaR ,wap ni nuG
,wons gnillaf dna ssenkrad eht ta derats eh sA
.aimrehtopyh gnitteg ydaerla er'uoY
.yb seog eh sa mih rof reehc dna hcterts gnitrats eht gnola ecalp a dnif ot si teb tseB
,ecap ni desaercni kcap eht fo gnicnuob ehT
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.egnar eht no ecitcarp fo sruoh rof lufknaht ,tnemevom eht rof etasnepmoc ot tseb sih did leafaR .yldliw
.etunim gnol a rof gnirewsna tuohtiw yks gnicnad eht ta derats eH
.dluoc eh sa duol sa delley leafaR
.tellaw sih detacol eh litnu taoc knip sih edisni dnuora tlef leafaR ".ereh
.55:11 .hctaw sih ta decnalg dna detnap leafaR ".mih
.daeh s'eaM htiw enil ni nihc sti tup ti
,meht evoba snevaeh eht hguorht yaw rieht gnuws seuh gniremmihS
.guh raeb evissam a ni tsehc reh ot mih dezeeuqs dna gab eht fo tuo mih depoocs eaM ,dnopser dluoc leafaR erofeB .deksa eaM "?retteb tahT" .demmid thgil eht dna ,kcilc nottub a draeh leafaR
.stoob sih rednu dehcnurc klawedis eht no wons ehT
.htaerb hcae morf sreksihw sih no demrof slatsyrc ecI
.mih htiw kaeps I taht si ti tnatropmi woh aedi on evah uoY .hcum os uoy knahT"
.kcab gnikcilf rae eno ,esirprus ni nepo depag elzzum reH
.sdeerb nrehtron naciremA eht lla gnoma god naisA na ssim ot draH .did I ,haeY"
.neeb dah ti thguoht eh erehw tuoba tsac dna sevolg sih ffo deppir eH
,gab eht fo tuo daeh sih dekop leafaR
,wons gnillaf yb derucsbo tsomla
swap s'eaM rednu wons fo gnihcnurc eht naht rehtO
.won pots nac uoY"
.tsehc reh ssorca smra reh gnissorc
".ydnah nug eralf taht peek dna hO"
?uoy ekil yug elttil A"
,raew retniw fo noitceles egral a yrrac yltcaxe t'ndid xineohP
,ecar s'raey tsal fo renniw eht si norbac tahT"
-dna ieW gnaW si eman siH
.pu deworrub leafaR
,tniopkcehc eht ot teg ew erofeb sruoh wef rehtona llits s’ti dna yellA esooM fo tuo er'eW"
.mih no gnippets ot esolc emac neve eno on esuaceb
leg lacimehc a s’tI"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.meht no nwod gnilerrab esoom delcsum fo llaw taht gniees nopu decneirepxe d'eh rorret eht raen gnihtyna tlef reven d'eh tub
.gninepo llams eht hguorht tif dluow taht lla
.melborp a llits saw ezis llams nwo sih ,revewoH
.esoom eht eltrats tub gnihton enod dah eralf siH
nwod dna pu gnicnuob saw kcapkcab eht dna ,noisiv sih derucsbo wons dna dniw gnippihw ehT
.wons eht no nwod yltneg mih tes neht dna tuo mih detfil ehS
.ecaf sih ni gniggaw sliat dna sgel yrruf tub gnihtyna ees t'ndluoc leafaR
.dleif nepo ediw a hguorht nar won eaM
,pirg sih ni gnitrofmoc saw lotsip a fo pirg railimaf ehT
.serutarepmet orezbus eseht ni etauqedani yllatot dna retniw anozirA mraw a rof tcefreP
,nwod dewols eaM ebyam ro
,mih revo mool ot pu kcab doots dna delwocs lrig yksuh ehT
.omma fo hcuop reppiz elttil s'nug eht dnuof eh litnu dnuora tlef dna
,deffuh eaM "!nwod yatS"
.epat reirrab citsalp yb dworc eht morf detarapes saw elbat eht fo tfel eht ot aera ehT
.tekcaj dna tah sih hguorht thgir eltsihw ot gnimees
,sgod gnissap fo gnisrevnoc eht ,elcycrotom gninnug a fo rednuht gnidnuop eht tnaem mih ot thgin dna
;god reggib a rof dezis saw nug ehT
.secnuob neewteb tuo dekrab leafaR ",tnaem I tahw ton s'tahT ?tahW" ".aday ,adaY
.ni knus dias dah god eht tahw erofeb yawa nrut ot detrats dna
,seiceps etanimretedni fo gniht yggahs gib a ,eibbac ehT
.tnemom a rof nepo gnipag elzzum reh ,mih ta derats eaM ".ecar
.bac eht edistuo klawedis eht nwod demaerts sgod fo sdworC
.tnemeticxe ni deppiy leafaR "!eaM ,ti tog I"
"!gnirevihs er'uoY"
.hsad sih no thgil 'eraf' eht tih tub daeh sih koohs eibbac ehT
.swap sih htiw edisni gab eht dedaenk dna gnitaoc citsalp detnirp eht ffo deppir leafaR ".antnewkS
.kcapkcab eht yb delffum dnuos eht ,dekrab eaM
tfos dna mraw yllufrednow saw ehS
ta tniopkcehc eht ot kcab og ot resolc s'ti kniht I
.htaerb fo trohs ylraelc
.elitcejorp gninrub eht egdolsid ot troffe na ni edis ot edis morf daeh sti gnikahs ,nwod dewols dna esirprus ni dekrab esoom ehT .ssih a htiw tsrub dna eson s'esoom eht otni dehsams thgil ehT
.noitseuq eht deksa dna erutcip eht pu dleh leafaR tub ,gninaem rieht tsol ecnis gnol dah sdrow ehT
.retnuH eht ,noirO saw erehT .loohcs edarg ni tuoba denrael d'eh snoitalletsnoc tuo kcip ot nageb eH
dnuora daeh sih denarc eH
",kcapkcab ruoy ni m'I"
”sthgileD nrehtroN“   yojne esaelP
.yruf gnigrahc fo snot eerht s'esoom eht ta neht lotsip citsalp ,egnaro eht ta dekool leafaR .eaM
.dluoc eh sa duol sa delwoh leafaR "!eaM !eaM"
.leafaR ekow taht gnicnuoj eht saw ti tub
.thgil eht sdrawot
.enut yhctac eht ffo gnittuc ,derewsna eh ",arierreF evitceteD dehcaer ev'uoY"
,ssenevigrof reh geb dna eaM ot ezigolopa ot detnaw leafaR
.flesmih rohtua eht yb
.god reggib eht ta pu neht dna enohp eht ta hteet sih derab leafaR
.tey regnad fO" .htaerb peed a koot ehS ".tuo toN"
,sserp eht otni drawrof dewolp dna ieW gnaW fo otohp sih pu dleh leafaR
.reh fo tnorf ni tsil a dekcehc dna kcab otohp eht mih dednah etumalam ehT ".ecar ot pu dengis swohc ynam evah t'noD .mih ezingocer I"
taoc reh fo tekcop eht fo tuo pam dedlof a dellup neht ,seert eht dna wons gnilriws eht ta meht dnuora dekool ehS
.mih nraw ot evah I .mih no tuo tih a s'erehT"
.nug eralF" .dekrab eaM "!faR"
.hsubma na fo su denraw eH
.raey hcae desahc teg sgod fo elpuoc A
"?uoy era woh dna ,ssob ,taerg m'I" .deworran seye
"?taht dias ohW ?tahW"
niap dna aesuan eht emacrevo noitom cimhtyhr eht dna htmraw eht yllautnevE
.nori looc naht rehtar citsalp eht fo gnileef egnarts eht etipsed
.rethgual ni delwoh eH
,pu deps dna deffuhw esoom ehT
.seno ykcul eht fo eno m'I sseuG
tlef leafaR flesmih etipseD ".naidraug
gnissim saw tah sih tub
".gab a ni taeH !gnizamA"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,epacsdnal eht dewollaws thgin eht pmaldaeh DEL s'eaM fo eralg eht dnoyeB
,mih evoba elbisiv emaceb eloh A
.noitanicsaf htiw ti ta derats leafaR "?ti si tahW"
.god tsrif eht naht erom on wenk tub
.won yltneloiv gnirevihs saw eH .deddon leafaR
.uoy nraw t'ndid I yas t'nod tuB
4 traP # .ecalp tsrif eht ni poc a emoceb d'eh yhw rebmemer mih edam tI
.deppots gnicnuob ehT ".tuo em teL"
.kcap leg citsalp erauqs egral a mih gnissap erofeb tekcop edistuo na htiw delddif neht dna
”sthgileD nrehtroN“
,daeh sih tsniaga kcab talf srae sih dellup eH
,reh ot resolc dehcni leafaR ".ecar
.tuo gnibmilc erofeb ytnewt a eibbac eht dednah leafaR ".egnahc
.dnuorg eht ot nwod elttes ti tlef leafaR dna ,debbob dna deyaws kcapkcab ehT
.mra reh gnippihw ,liat sih deggaw eH
"!seiksuh diputs esoht ,hO" .delworg eH
.eaM ot seigolopa dna margnI sevas dna sdnif leafaR woh tuo dnif ot
.dias eciov elamef a
.ycnegru citnarf htiw kcap s'eaM otni kcab gud leafaR "!pleH .gaB
dias "?eb ot desoppus uoy era lleh eht tahW"
.noitazilivic ot kcab uoy teg ot woh tuo erugif ot tog ev'I ,teiuq woN
.srecar eht ekil ,sdeerb nrehtron lla ,sgod gib eerht erew ti dniheb deyarrA
.gab eht fo tuo thgir ecnuob eh tsel no barg ot dah eh hcum os dnuora mih gniltsoj
.egdab sih yksuh eht wohs ot tuo ti gnitfil
.kciht oot eb t'now dworc eht erehw ecalp doog a wonk I
.sgod gib rehto eerht fo gnir a otni mih del yksuh ehT
.dniw eht fo lwoh eht revo draeh eb ylerab dluoc pmub hcae dehctam taht dnuos pmuht
.emit drah a meht evig ot deirt esoom rehtona esac ni gnitiaw dna ydaer
.meht dniheb thgin eht otni deraeppasid tsaeb eht dna ,gninnur deunitnoc eaM
emit txen ni enuT
.dekaeuqs leafaR "?tahW"
,ti daoler ot deganam eh
.pmuj dna pley mih edam hcuot thgil-rehtaef reh nevE
.ti denepo dna revo dehcaer yksuh eht litnu eloh dehcnic eht ta niaga dehctarcs dna delworg leafaR
,sgnidliub fo spot eht ees ylno dluoc eh yltsoM
mih fo daeha gniklaw etumalam detsehc-lerrab etihw dna yarg A
.mih delbmuh dna dewa thgis ehT
.nirg s'eaM gninruter flesmih
"?noitcerid sih ni em tniop uoy naC !lufrednoW"
.ieW gnaW gnidnif ot resolc yna nettog t'ndah leafaR dna
.yks eht ta ylgnicanem hteet sih derab leafaR
.yrrow t'nod os ,no eunitnoc ot htob su stifeneb tI"
.ti dnuof eh erofeb stnemom lareves rof dnuora elbmuf ot dah eh tnaem gnipmub dna gnikahs eht tub
.niaga ti tuhs neht tub ,eaM ot hcum sa yas ot elzzum sih denepo eH
.dloc eht morf ton dna gnikahs saw eH
thgin eht fo krad eht ni thgirb os saw thgil ehT
.erusolcne decnef rieht ni ooz eht ta nosrep ni meht nees neve
,dniw eht ni seert enip gnidnuorrus eht fo gnihsuhs eht dna
.tuo daeh sih deppop dna seye sih deworran leafaR
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.yrettab eht tuo dellup dna kcab eht ffo deppop leafaR nehw yltpurba ffo tuc hcihw ,niaga gnar enohp ehT .pu gnuh leafaR ".ycnegreme
.dniw eht ni demaerts kcen sti morf gnignah niks fo palf ehT
"--yeht ylerus ,seitirohtua naksalA eht tuoba tahW"
.sehsal sih morf slatsyrc eci epiw dna ,eson dna srae sih mraw ot gab eht otni kcab dekcud leafaR
.emit ni mih dnif reven ll'uoY ?dworc taht nI
,meht naht reggib hcum os saw ti tub
,eloh eht derevoc taht palf htolc eht tsniaga desserp daeh siH
.dloc leef ot gnitrats saw leafaR ,gnidaf saw esoom eht htiw regnad eht morf enilanerda eht taht woN ".tey
teef fo riap eno naht erom morf emac yeht ekil dednuos spetstoof gnihcnurc eht tub
taht ti ssorca rennab a htiw elbat gnol a yb tuo mih tips dworc eht fo edit eht yllaniF
.eaM otni sehsarc sih fo ycneuqerf eht hctam t'ndid ecnedac eht sa
,detrats ecar eht erofeb ieW gnaW hctac ot ecnahc sih tsol ydaerla d'eH
".sevael eh erofeb mih ot klat I tnatropmi yllativ s'tI .recar a s'eH
.srae yffulf s'eaM revo tuo dekool eh litnu
.dnuora deltsoj gnieb saw eh elihw ffo nellaf evah tsum hcihw
".adilas yah on eliab etse 'aP" .abmuZ fo senil tsrif eht gnignis ramO noD tuo gnitleb ,gnar llec siH
mih dediug ti morf gnimoc ezeerb dloc ehT
.redwop tfos eht otni tsrif ecaf despalloc eH
.seye reh ni truh eht ees dluoc leafaR ".uoy ton ,hO"
.nwod demlac ehs gniraews fo setunim erom wef a retfA
,kcapkcab s'god egral a sa dezingocer won eh tahw fo noitcetorp eht fo edistuO
,kcap-leg mraw yllufssilb eht tsniaga ecaf sih sserp dna gab eht otni kcab daeh sih kcud ot gnivah saw yltnatsnoc eH
.dias eaM ",yrros ,spoO"
.taes sih otni kcab delttes dna dias leafaR ",enil gnitrats doratidI" "?ot erehW"
.auhauhihC elttil eht ta nwod erats ot denrut dna deltrats
.bruc eht morf yawa dellup dna deggurhs god yggahs ehT
.doots dna tlebtaes sih ffo deppop leafaR
"!em esucxe ,em esucxE"
.antnewkS ot no eunitnoc naht rehtaR"
.yellA esooM sa nwonk si aera siht ,haeY"
.mih nees t'nevaH"
.derutseg dna liat sih deggaw xim yksuh ehT
.potelbat eht evoba tuoba wap a devaw leafaR sa mih ta decnalg etumalam yarg krad A "?uoy pleh I naC"
.swodniw eht yb detfird sekalf giB
,enalp a no ydaerla saw eh tub ,tfel eh erofeb mih llac ot deirt I .wonk I"
.tsehc sih ot efink a ekil saw htaerb hcae digirf os saw ria ehT
.dnuora sgod rehto yna ees t'ndluoc eh dna saw eh erehw aedi on dah eH
.antnewkS ot teg ew litnu mraw dna ecin uoy peek dna pu taeh lliw ti dna gnigakcap eht ffo ekaT .remraw
,klat ot doom eht ni t'nsaw ehs llet dluoc leafaR ".oN"
,reivaeh tlef gab ym yhw derednow I
.mih draeh t'ndah ehs spahreP
.kcab sih nwod wons fo lriws a gnidnes ,deltsihw dniw ehT
.pu leafaR ekow eltsoj prahs A
.renetfos cirbaf dna ykrej fo gnillems
.ycnegreme ylimaF
.sedis sih ot swap sih desiar dna leafaR ecaf ot denrut eH
.bruc eht ot revo dellup eibbac ehT ".uoy
.gnisuac saw siht yaled eht ta noitartsurf ni delworg tsomla leafaR
.kcap s'lrig eht otni kcab bmilc ot detpmet
kcapkcab eht otni nwod kcab delggiw leafaR
.gnillenS ieW gnaW rof gnikool m'I"
.duola nekops d'eh dezilaer t'ndah eH
,snroh gib dah dna ,erus ,evissam erew yehT
.gnineppah toN ?tahW"
.ruf yarg ro etihw dah meht fo tsom taht tcaf eht yb reisae edam saw boj sih hguohtla edis rehto eht no tuoba dellim sgod fo sderdnuH
.sliart eht esu ot ekil esoom eht os esned si tserof ehT
.deniur neeb dah doom eht ,etal oot saw ti tuB
.lekoy derutlucnu na ekil dnuos ot tnaw t'ndid eH
,sserp eht ni seippup rellams rof gnihctaw ot desu erew aksalA fo sgod gib eht ro
.dias leafaR ",dloc tsuJ"
.deifirret os neeb reven dah leafaR
.htnom tsal rentrap ym dna em fo efil eht devas noitamrofni s'ieW gnaW"
,ezag rats ot sniatnuom eht ot pu mih nekat dah rehtaf sih ,yppup a saw eh nehW
.sregnessap rof gnitiaw bruc eht ta gnildi sbac eht fo eno fo kcab eht otni depmuj leafaR
".hcum siht mih ewo I"
.seert enip krad yb dednuorrus ,knabwons a ni gnittis saw eH
,taes sih ni pu tas leafaR
,nepo ti deppilf dna tuo ti dellup eH
".uoy htiw og ot deen I"
.nretnal daeh reh fo thgil eht htiw mih gnidnilb ,mih
?he ,thgis eht etiuQ"
krowrepap emoceb dah boj sih fo hcum os yletaL
keeW krahS detide dna
.dniw eht fo gnilwoh eht revo sdrow reh tuo ekam ylerab dluoc leafaR reh dniheb thgir morf nevE ".suoregnaD .esooM"
,emit thgir eht ta ,ecalp thgir eht ni mih tup dah ti tuB
,taoc knip sih ni mraw saw leafaR
.pam reh pu kcab dedlof eaM ".aimrehtopyh
.daeh reh koohs dna deffuh ehS
,detaeper ssob sih ",evitceted era uoy erehw deksa I"
.sregnif sih dnuora seye sih denrub llits sDEL ehT
"?god siht nees uoy evah ,ris ,esaelP"
,wons gnirettilg eht no detcelfer srats eht fo thgil ehT
spit eht taht os sreltna talf ,ediw sti gniretnec ,daeh sti derewol esoom ehT
,nug eht detfil dna sehsaleye sih no gnimrof erew taht slatsyrc eci eht yawa gniknilb ,derevihs leafaR
.enil gnitrats eht sdrawot sgod fo sserp eht dewollof dna
.elims reh leef dluoc eh tub ,srae reh fo spit eht dna daeh reh fo kcab eht saw reh fo ees dluoc leafaR llA
"?god siht nees uoy evah ,em esucxE"
.gnirevihs sih pots ot hguone mraw emaceb tsomla leafaR ,steknalb reh ni deldnub dna daeh sih no kcab taht htiW
".ti gnipleh on s'ereht tub ,eludehcs dniheb em tup lliw tI
,nug eralf eht gnidaol dehsinif eh retfa
,mih ediseb ni llef leafaR
.nrut neddus a edam bac eht sa rood eht ta debbarg leafaR ".kciht
.kcapkcab eht pu kcab gnisolc nageb eaM ".edisni
.naidraug trawlats a gnola dah I gniht dooG"
.sdrawretfa kcap ruoy ni em deffuts sseug I dna...daeh
.seye s'eaM tem dna delworg leafaR "!oN"
.seert mlap dna ytic gib ruoy ot kcab teg ot tiaw t'nac uoy dna
,reggirt eht dnuora regnif a teg ylerab dluoc leafaR
.ten.relleknosidam no
.sduolc eht dniheb neddih yletelpmoc nus eht ,yarg saw yks eht daehrevO
,taht neht dnA
.ylivaeh dehgis neht
.dworc eht hguorht ecap ksirb a ta ffo koot god eht sa pu peek ot ylsuoiruf sgel sih gnipmup
.nwod em wols ot gniyrt saw ylbaborp eH
.resolc ti gnillup ,ti debbarg eh dna ,drah gnihtemos dehsurb wap siH
,egar htiw gnireviuq slwoj
.ruf ruoy ot esolc s’ti fi tseb skrow ti ,oslA"
.ysub m'I ,yawa og woN
.deffuh eaM "!yr...ruH"
.ffo reh ssip ot tnaw t'ndid eH
.ecar eht rof anozirA morf ereh
nwod looc ot ecnahc a dah d'ehs ecno ,antnewkS ta ygolopa na reh evig d'eH
,mih detsalb ria dloc eht sa derevihs eh rood eht denepo eh nehW
.esor selkcah sih hguohtla ylneve mih derewsna leafaR ",auhauhihC a m'I" .dranreB tniaS etihw dna nworb gnirewot a
.flesmih dnuora dekool dna pu tas eH
.ylippah deddon dna denethgirb leafaR ".ereht
.kcab s'eaM otni yldetaeper mih gnimmals
,krad eht ni dnuora gnilbmuf fo tol a retfA
.mra sih fo koorc eht otni elzzum sih deworrub dna seye sih morf sraet deknilb eH
.temoc a ekil tegrat sti sdrawot gnimaerts
.daeh sih fo kcab eht no pmub eht ta deborp dna pu dehcaer leafaR
,skcih fo lluf retawkcab gnirob a s'aksalA .wonk I"
.kcab nups dna dekrej eH
,mih ta seye reh deworran dna delworg eaM
.mrah morf god tneconni na tcetorp ot
.ieW gnaW gnimood ylbissop dna
.wodniw eht tuo ees ot gnilggurts
"!gnol selim derdnuh enin revo si etuor ehT
.hteet reh gnirab dna daeh reh no talf kcab gniog srae
.htnom tsal sreifilauq eht ni mih fo daeha ni emac I ecnis reve em etadimitni dna yllub ot gniyrt neeb s'margnI .paY margnI
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.god siht dnif I taht tnatropmi yllativ s’ti dnA"
,mih deciton ohw god tsrif eht
".rof enod neeb evah thgim I ,ereh neeb t'ndah uoy fI
.emid ruoY" ".tnatropmi s'tI
,rehtruf llits daeh sti derewol esoom ehT
.desolc ylnrobbuts deniamer hcihw
.daeh sih ni gnidnuop eht htiw detepmoc
.mih ta kcab dennirg leafaR
.nemecilop rehto saw tI
.denaw dah thgil eht tub ,gnillaf llits saw wonS
ta ni nwod dereep eaM retal tnemom a dna eltsoj kcapkcab eht tlef leafaR
,erows lrig yksuh ehT
,pu yaw sih dewalc dna cirbaf gnitcirtsnoc eht fo eerf thguof leafaR
.ereht revo tiaw lla srennur ehT
.tuo flesmih dellup d'eh sa edis sih otni gniggid egde citsalp drah a gnileef derebmemer d'eH
.ecar eht gnirud neppah ot gniog s'ti taht si noitanissassa eht tuoba tuo dnif ot elba saw I elttil tahW
.bulcthgin noen yduag a hguorht gninnur erew yeht ekil gnihsalf dna gnicnad elprup dna neerg
.deil leafaR ",gnihton saw tI"
.yaw sih gnikcolb wons eht ni modnar ta ylgnimees delip erew seilppus dna skcapkcab fo sdaol ,esrow nevE
.esoom taht htiw taerg did uoY"
.mra sih sa gnol sa tsomla saw ti dna 'remraw waP' delebal saw kcap raelc ehT
gnirekcilf srae reh ,delkcuhc eaM
”sthgileD nrehtroN“
,ksed sih ta gnittis mih erutcip dluoc leafaR dna llubtip a saw niatpaC ehT
"?kcapkcab ym uoy ni era yhw ,yppup woN“
"?uoy era tar adnik tahW"
.deffuh eaM ",uoy draeH"
.yksuh elamef egral a fo seye eht otni pu derats leafaR
.emit eht lla gnillaf saw wons erom tub ,delevohs erew sklawedis ehT
,mih fo daeha kcolb a ecnatsid eht nI
.sseug I ,thgirla s'ti ,haeY"
.pu taeh ot nageb ti yletaidemmi tsomlA
.tfel reh ot detniop neht ehS ".hguorht
.ieW gnaW fo ngis
"?srennur eht htiw wohc wohc nedlog egral a ees uoy diD"
.egdab tnemtrapeD eciloP xineohP sih pu gnidloh elihw elbat eht no ti tup ot seotpit sih no doots dna
.tca ot stnemom ylno dah eh wenk leafaR tub
.foow duol a htiw ffo mih tuc dranreB ehT "-
.daeh sih derewol leafaR dna
.meht fo erom eb thgim ereht rO
.god gib a dias ",evah I ,haeY ?miH"
,boj sti did tekcaj noen sih rehtiE
.slirtson gnivaeh sti morf deppird dna ruf yggahs s’tsaeb eht morf gnuh slatsyrc ecI
dias leafaR ",yawyna sknahT"
.egnahc eht peeK .sknahT"
.taht od t'ndid sratS
,tfel eh erofeb mih nraw ot gnipoh ,ereh mih dewollof I
.tnelis saw thgin eht
".tser eht wonk uoy ,llew dna ,em tih norbac taht
.mih evoba erehwemos morf gnimoc
.mih denoituac eaM ",swalc ruoy htiw ti erutcnup ot ton luferaC"
setunim wef rehtona rof nar eaM .esac ni tsuj
.rac gnissap a morf gnikael esab gnilbmur eht dna
.tnemtrapeD eciloP xineohP eht htiw arierreF leafaR evitceteD m'I"
.rac gnissap eht htaeneb steerts eht ni hsuls ot dnuorg saw dna sgnidliub eht tsniaga hgih delip saw wonS
.ffuh a dna kcilc elbidua na htiw htuom reh desolc ehS
.derevesrep eh tub
.ecanruf a htiw nwod gniyl ekil saw eaM htiw gnieb tuB .mih hguorht thgir og ot gnimees
,ksed a dniheb enod
.efil dna boj sih htiw detcennoc os tlef d'eh emit tsal eht rebmemer t'ndluoc eh dezilaer eh dna
knarp siht gnillup rof margnI ta dam llits saw eH
"?sgnikram nat thgil htiw etihw yltsom redaeL ?seiksuh eerhT"
?thgir ,tuo uoy spleh taht lanimirc emos tsuj si ieW gnaW siht dna evitceted a er'uoY" .detrons eaM ".mih
.taes eht otni delttes leafaR sa ekat elbuod a did
.nepo deppilf eloh eht gnirevoc palf eht neht dna kcilc a saw ereht
.retsulc a syawla si aera kcab ehT
.elims htuom ediw a mih evag dna htaerb a tuo welb eaM ".seno
.knarp leurc siht ot thgilyad gnisol saw eh won dna
.nosrep ni ieW gnaW nraw ot deen I
.derevocer ti ecno meht esahc ot eunitnoc thgim tI
.rehtie dluoc reve eh kniht t'ndid eh taht dettimda dna wohs thgil s'erutan ta pu kcab dekool leafaR
.cirbaf fo palf a yb derevoc
.ereht sreetnulov eht htiw ni kcehc ot evah gnicar sgod eht lla os ,tniopkcehc a s'tI
.leafaR ta thgir detniop
.kaeps ot detrats leafaR sa wap a pu dleh dna hgis gib a evag ehS ".nwod
.dnaletsaw nezorf a otni dna tropria eht fo tuo deklaw leafaR
god wohc derruf nedlog a fo otohp yssolg a tuo dellup leafaR
.liava on htiw mih dnuora sgod reggib eht fo yna fo noitnetta eht teg ot gniyrt ,delley leafaR
,xineohP nwotnwod fo steerts naem eht no slanimirc fo erahs sih nwod decaf d'eH
”...dna gnitrats saw ecar eht tub
,ti nepo ot woh wenk eh kcap eht fo edistuo eht nees d'eh taht woN
.teef tnereffid xis fo gnidduht eht hsiugnitsid dna
.antnewkS sa raf sa uoy ekat ll'I
.tsehc sih ni deremmah traeh siH
.yawa spets sih deirruh neht dna deknilb etumalam ehT
.gnidnuop llits saw traeh siH
...daeh eht ni em tih yehT .seiksuh eerht ot gniklat saw I"
# .wons eht detcapmi eh erofeb tuo saw eH
.daeh eht fo kcab eht ni mih tih yvaeh gnihtemos
etilop erom elttil a saw ,srae ralugnairt htiw god omiksE etihw a ,god txen ehT
,pirg reh otni dexaler leafaR dna
.yksuh fo dnik emos eb thgim eh thguoht tub erus t'nsaw leafaR
rehto yna ees t'ndid tub ,dnuora decnalg eH
,dloc eht etipseD
uoy rof daer ,2 fo 1 traP
.enog dah tah sih erehw gnirednow
.gniod saw eaM tahw dezilaer eh
"!mih ot thgir uoy ekat nac I
.pmaldaeh s'eaM fo snoitcelfer yltsohg htiw dewolg ria eht ni gnilriws wons eht
.auhauhihC a tif taht sezis ni yllaicepse
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.daehrevo ylthgirb gnilkniwt srats fo sderdnuh ees dluoc eh ,kcab daeh sih denarc leafaR nehW
,ytic gib eht ni pu nworg d'eH
.sllabeye sih ta gnippin dna eson sih gnizeerf yltnatsni ,ni deppihw ria ralop ,eloh eht denepo dna eerf psalc eht dellup eh tnatsni ehT
,gab eht revo llef wodahs a sa demmid thgil ehT
,mih ot txen nwod dehcuorc eaM "?yhW
"?erac uoy od yhw oS
.tleb taes sih no deppans eh sa kcab dekrab leafaR ",dnik god ehT"
.revihs ot gnitrats ydaerla saw leafaR
.gnizeerf saw eh tah dna taoc eht htiw nevE
.yltcaxe ton ,gniyl t'nsaw eH
.dias eaM "?peels emos teg uoy t'nod yhw os
.eson sih gnuts dniw yci eht
...morf em devas ieW gnaW hsubma ehT"
.sserp eht hguorht teef fo elpuoc a naht erom ees t'ndluoc eH
.tsael ta sruoh rof tuo neeb d'eH
.reggirt eht dellup dna llits ot swap gnikahs sih delliw eH
.srats tsethgirb eht tub lla neddih dah ytic eht fo sthgil eht ereht neve tub
.uoy teem ot erusaelp a neeb ton s'ti tub yrros m'I dna ,eaM"
.ecaf ot ecaf ti od dluoc eh nehw dna
,pmuht ,pmuht ydaets A
.regnol hcum pu ecap siht peek t'ndluoc ehs suoivbo saw tI