,seldeen enip dna wons tub gnihton gnihctac
,pu kcab doots neht tnemom a rof sih tsniaga pu eson reh desserp ehS ".ygolopa
.enil eht ot denruter niatpaC eht neht ;dnuos delffum a saw erehT ".deednI"
.tnemtraped eht fo oreh sa sutats dna sunob gib a htiw gnola ,esiar a dna noitomorp a ta gnikool saw eh woN
.edisni reh dewollof leafaR
,dlot lla sgod nezod owt tuoba
.efil ot deraor elibomwons eht sa yawa deppets dna doots ehS
.deirt leafaR tub ,saw ti sa deirub ,liat sih gaw ot drah saw tI
.deggurhs aksiK ".mih retfa ksa ot gninrom siht god dnoces eht er'uoY"
.daeh sih evoba hgih tuo ti daerps dna dne rehtie ta skcits eht yb ti detfil eH
.rennab lyniv eht delrufnu leafaR
deggoj ehS .gab reh gnikcap dehsinif dah eaM
"?gniod uoy er'tahw ,eaM"
.nwod dewols eaM ,htap eht tfel skcart s'god eht erehw tniop eht dehcaer yeht sA
.seldeen enip nellaf fo deb tfos a otno kcap eht morf degreme leafaR dna
.deirc kwah a ecnatsid eht ni erehwemoS
.tniopkcehC antnewkS saw tnirp kcalb rellams ni htaenrednU
.yb og yrenecs eht hctaw ot gab eht edistuo daeh sih tpek eh dluoc eh sa hcum sa neht
.keehc eht no mih dekcep dna mih morf ti dekculp ehS
.yawa ti dehsup dna ffo thguoht taht tuc eH
.tuo ti nethgiarts ot tseb sih gniod
,god decneirepxe ssel a ot ecivda evig ot
kcen s'eaM dnuora smra sih worht ot dah eh hcum os dnuora decnuoj leafaR .stoob reh morf welf wonS
.pleh ot evom on edam esiwrehto tub
bac a ni deppoh eh
.kcap eht morf gniylf ksir ro
- a ton ,evitceted a tsuj m'I ,niatpaC"
.sehcturc sih htiw wons eht gnitagivan yldrawkwa
.flac s'margnI pu flesmih dellup dna ,waj sih denepo
.noitom htooms eno ni gab reh fo edis eht deppiznu eaM ".ydaerla
.nwod mih gnipparts erew yeht sa pu emac eaM
.mih ot txen nwod deppord eaM gninraw tuohtiW ".yrros m'I
"?gnikniht uoy erew tahW !margnI ,uoy dnA"
.sehsal sih morf selcici deknilb eh dna sffup elttil ni tuo emac htaerb siH
.kcapkcab eht ffo gnikat nageb dna dias eaM
,niaga mraw saw eh litnu ereht deyats eH
draobpilc a gnidloh omiksE naciremA deliat-ylruc ,etihw A
,gnisahc erew serugif derruf yarg dna etihw eerhT
".neht erofeb gnol mih hctac dluoc margnI dna ,tsenoos eht ta ,tniopkcehC ekaL regniF eht litnu ieW gnaW htiw pu teem ot elba eb t'ndluow uoY"
.efil eritne ym xineohP ni devil ev'I ,hturt eht llet oT
.erutcip eht ta gnicnalg ylerab ,mih ta depag aksiK
.kcapkcab eht fo tuo eson sih deppop dna llab sih morf delrucnu eH
,guh gnol a mih evag dna mih revo denael ehS
,detuohs dna ylediw delims leafaR
.skaerb gninnur reh fo eno gnirud mih ot dias eaM ",liart sthgiL nrehtroN eht fo trap si sihT"
.raeg roodtuo etairporppa-rehtaew wen sih ni mraw yltnasaelp saw eh dniw gniwolb dna wons eht etipseD
daeh s'leafaR evoba hgih ,esruoc fO
.pu emac nus eht erofeb tsuJ
ruf fo elip a rednu deirub saw eh wenk eh gniht txeN
.niaga ti tuhs neht ,mih htiw eugra ot elzzum reh denepo eaM ".ieW
.ytilanif htiw detaeper leafaR ",tiuq I"
.dias aksiK ",niaga ffo koot neht ,ni kcehc ot hguone gnol dnuora kcutS
.saw ti tnelis dna llits woh saw aksalA ni leafaR kcurts taht gniht enO
pu tes saw tnet god-eno lufroloc a ,desimorp sA
.boj sih tsol d'eh erus neeb d'eH "?em esucxE"
.no deppets gnieb diova ot gniyrt elihw sgod reggib eht neewteb taht dna yaw siht gnitrad
.ylpeed delahni eh daetsnI
,tnemom a rof tekcop sih no reppiz eht htiw delbmuf leafaR ".wohC
".emit ruoy ni oidar I litnu gnidnats llarevo ruoy wonk t'noW
,mih ta nwod erats ot denrut eldduh eht ni god yrevE
,sraey rof retfa neeb ev'ew sgod detserra ew thgin tsaL
.gel s'renwo eht otni hteet sih gniknis dna dnuora gnitsiwt ,tcnitsni no detcaer dna depley leafaR
.dias eaM ",doratidI eht ni gnihtyreve t'nsi tsaF"
.ereh mih taeb ew snaem ti nehT"
enip ,eci fo dellems ehs ,eson sih dellif tnecs reH
taoc sih ni pmul gnilooc a ot gninrut
.reehc eslaf htiw dias leafaR ",niatpaC ,gninrom dooG"
.ecaps eht fo tsom pu koot ydob yksuh yffulf s'eaM dna ,llams saw tnet ehT
.ten.relleknosidam no
neeb evah dluohs ti naht reduol demees ti dnuos a saw ereht nehw ,taht fo esuaceB
.eenk s'margnI fo dneb kcab eht ta thgir dluoc eh sa drah sa nwod tib neht
.teef fo kcart tsol eh taht seiksuh owt eht hsarht ieW gnaW gnihctaw ni dessorgne os saw eH
.lufituaeb dna ,denimreted ,evarb saw eaM
.nwod dna pu pmuj ot detnaw eh deticxe os ,meht htiw gnola eman s'eaM dekrab leafaR
.mih ta gnuws margnI
yrots s’yadoT dna
.xineohP ni tropria eht ta pu uoy kcip enoemos evah dna sthgilf nruter ruoy egnarra ll'I
.daeh sih evoba dleh llits nori erit eht
.niap ni decniw eH .gel sih deddorp yltneg dna revo dellor leafaR
esirprus ni nepo deppord selzzum rieht eno sa dna
".regnad ni si efil ruoy ,yaw eht yB .haH"
.tsac kciht a ni debmotne deb eht no dial gel nekorb siH
.klub s'margnI rednu gnitacoffus dna
.esu srennur eht liart eht no dewolla t'nerA" "--selibomwons ehT
".sremit tsrif no pu kcehc ot ekil yeht em dlot yehT .ees uoy
.edutitarg fo tbed eguh a eaM dewo eh niaga neht tub
pu dellor sih tfel leafaR
,noitcartsid ’srotnemrot sih fo egatnavda gnikat dna
.tah sih tsol evah tsum eh tniop emos ta taht dezilaer dna
.ereh saw eh yhw dna deneppah dah tahw nialpxe ot elihw a etiuq leafaR koot tI
.enif tub ,pu desiurb elttil A .enif s'eH"
,reh morf gnitaidar taeh eht leef dluoc eh eaM ot esolc siht gnieB
.noitardyhed dna aimrehtopyh dlim morf gnireffus saw eh
.mrof ehtil s'eaM otni gnivloser yllautneve
.wons eht htaeneb morf dekop seldeen eert-enip neerg dna eulb fo sehsalF
.pu mih dellup dna
".tuo daeh ll'ew dna pu kcab kcap ot setunim wef a em eviG
,eiree saw deohce dnuos yaw ehT
.anozirA tfel reve ev'I emit tsrif eht si sihT
fael yhcnurc dna ,enoc-enip ,hcnarb ,giwt yreve no deppets evah tsum eH
.kcap s’eaM recar ni mih tup dna tuo mih dekconk taht seillub fo puorg a yb ieW gnaW nraw ot
.xineohP ni tnemtrapa sih pu kcap ot srevom gnillac yllanif dna
.ylper s'margnI fo tser eht tuo denword selibomwons fo raor ehT
,reh ekil lrig a ta tohs a evah reven d'eh dias evah d'eh gninrom sihT
.srecar suoirav rof srennab dleh emoS
.pu ydob rewol sih llup ot gniyrt
.reh rof nettog d'eh tfig eht dnuof eh litnu edisni dnuora detoor dna kcapkcab sih ffo gnuls eh niaga ydaets saw eh ecnO
.emos dedisbus gnirevihs siH
.deilper niatpaC eht ",ereht pu krow doog
.kcul fo tuo er'uoy ria yb emac uoy fi ,yawynA"
.tniopkcehc txen eht ot em htiw uoy ekat ot em ksa ot gniog er’uoy txen esoppus I ,oS"
.tih sgod rehto eht sa niap ni derepmihw eh dna ,taoc nedlog s'ieW gnaW dekaerts doolB .ecaf sih revo swap tnorf sih ,llab a otni delruc dah ieW gnaW
.wohC nedlog a s'eH .ieW gnaW si eman siH .god siht rof gnikool m'I"
.kcapkcab reh ffo llup ot nwod tlenk dna deppots eaM elihw ffo ti dehsurb eH
.meht derongi leafaR
eldnub a fo llams woh dna kcapkcab reh dekcap d'ehs tsaf woh ta gnilevram elihw
stpmetta sih ni detrawht saw auhauhihC eht leafaR ,emit tsaL
.tniopkcehc eht ot mih taeb
.sdoow eht otni god derruf dlog htruof a ,yllaer gnidreh
.kcits ot segrahc teg ot elba neeb reven tub
.daeh sih koohs leafaR ".tniopkcehc
.emac gnitcepxe neeb d'eh llac eht gninrom txen eht ylraE
nori erit a pu dekcip margnI dehctaw yeht sA
.steknalb ni mih gnireyal
,nwo ym fo seippup teg dna etam a dnif reven d'I taht detnemal yehT .eninimef-
,taht ta god deerb ngierof a dna
.ffo mih gnittuc ,dias eaM ",sdaor eht no yats ot evah yehT
,selibomwons eht fo eno fo kcab eht ot dehcatta rehcterts a otno mih dedaol dna gel s'leafaR detnilps cidem ehT
,eugitaf ni neknus seye reh
.redrum detpmetta fo segrahc no srebmem kcap sih dna margnI tserra ot deerga ecilop lacol eht
.tniopkcehc eht ta kaerb a gnikat srennur rehto eb ot meht degduj leafaR dna skcapkcab erow wef A
.kcab ti gnittup erofeb tnemom a rof ti ta derats dna rae sih morf yawa enohp eht dellup leafaR
.gnineffits selkcah sih ,dias leafaR
,ressik citsatnaf a saw eaM
-" .pu deps dna ,deffuh ehs "--t'nsaw tI"
.peels emos teg tub ,raf os em nevig ev'uoy pleh eht etaicerppa I ,eaM"
.daeh s'leafaR revo depmuj dna delrans eaM .niagA
.elzzum ot elzzum ,mih no ssik a detnalp dna yawa dellup neht
.mih tsap ti tup t'ndluow I ,revewoH"
.taht tuoba hguone dias ydaerla I kniht I ,llew
aksalA fo sdoowkcab eht ni pu gniworg tuoba lla mih dlot eaM dna ,noitasrevnoc tnasaelp a dah yehT
.daeh s'leafaR no nwod gniyarps wons fo yrrulf llams
.kcap reh fo mottob eht ot deit neeb dah taht gab gnipeels elyts gab-ydob a tuo koohs ehs sa mih deksa eaM "?swen dooG"
wons fo raelc ylevitaler saw seert eht htaenrednu aera ehT
6 traP # .ssik a mih welb dna devaw ehS
.ti no stoob ynam os morf nwod dekcap saw hcra nedoow eht dnuora wons ehT
.dnim sih otni deppop taht drow tsrif eht saw ti
.emoh morf yaw gnol a er'uoY .ym ,hO" ".anozirA morF"
.wons eht otni depmots margnI
.esrow dna swen dab ,oN"
.kcawht llud a emac wons eht no stoob s'eaM fo sehcnurc eht neewteB .deirrac ti dna
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.aet toh fo snollag ekil tlef tahw knird mih edam dna steknalb mraw ni mih depparw d'yehT
.yad taht retal ni gnimoc reh dah snoitciderp eht tub
.enohp eht no pirg sih denethgit eH
".eno siht fo tuo lesaew ot elba eb t'now yeht ,lleW
.dloc eht tsniaga pu deldnub
.elims eniuneg a htiw deilper leafaR ",yhw ees nac I"
.enil eht fo dne rehto eht hguorht emac ecnelis daeD ".tiuq I"
.duol ylgninefaed saw ffo gniog nug-eralf eht fo ssih dna pop eht ,ecnelis neddus eht nI
.nettib d'eh ohw kcehc ot kniht eh did retfa ylnO
,hcamots sih no margnI dah eaM eerf delwarc eh emit eht yB
.sgod reggib eht naht sevlesruo evorp ot erom od ot evah ew ,sey tuB"
.saw ehs ereh tey
.gel s'margnI otni ylpeed gnitib ,redrah nwod htuom sih dnuorg eH .reh ton tub ,s'eaM ot ralimis saw tnecs ehT
.mih tih ria dloc eht sa pirg reh tsniaga delggurts leafaR
"?t'nsah eh fi dnA" ".wonk ll'ehs
,kcab eht no ssorc etihw a htiw tekcaj der a erow god dranreB tniaS yffulf egral A
,setunim neetfif ekil erom ylbaborp saw tub ,gel gnibborht sih dna leafaR ot sruoh ekil tlef tahw retfA ".ereh si yrlavaC"
,gniliaf saw kcap leg siH
.liat sih fo pit eht thguac dna nwod depmots toob A
.pmots ot deraperp ,gel sih detfil margnI .doolb detsat eH
eht hguorht dereep dna reh ot txen pu deppets leafaR
hgual ossab gnilbmur a tuo tel ieW gnaW esnopser nI
anozirA mraw ot kcab hsur d'uoy thguoht I
",wohC taht ,yug ralupoP"
.evititepmoc ylsselhtur si margnI"
srae ytniop sih fo pit eht hsurb ti tlef eH
,mih naht regral semit eerht tsael ta saw ehs taht tcaf eht etipseD
"!ecilop ,potS" ,gnituohs drawrof deppets neht dna
,erutcip s'ieW gnaW htiw gnola
.kcen sih dnuora mra eno dna kcab sih ni eenk reh
.deksa leafaR "?laed gib eht saw tahW"
.txet der thgirb ni ti no detnirp saw noipmahC eht eaM
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,rennur emit tsrif a no pu gnikcehc saw margnI taht uoy dlot I fI"
.daeh reh dekcoc dna nwod denael aksiK ".si ti ,seY"
,meht ot tuo llac aksiK draeh leafaR tfel yeht sA
.wons eht tsniaga kceps a ,ecnatsid eht ni deraeppa erugif A
.wons fo esnapxe dehcuotnu tsomla eht no thgirb dna gnirettilg thgil eht ,ecnatsid eht ni noziroh eht revo gnikeep ylerab saw nus ehT
.thguoht ehs sa gnikcilf srae reh ,daeh reh dekcoc aksiK ".uoy
noitciF degnaF yb dehsilbup seires seidoB gnignahC eht etorw ohw
.esrun eht morf tes-dnah elbatrop eht koot dna ,flesmih deleets ,deplug leafaR
.sgel trohs sih htiw pu peek ot tseb sih did leafaR
.ria dloc eht ni gnimaets htaerb reh ,detnap ehs sa tuo gnuh eugnot reH
gel nekorb sih htiw gnola dias yehT
.wons ylkraps htiw detaroced
.ecar eht fo dne laiciffo eht dekram taht gniht nedoow taerg a
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.stnirp-wap rieht ni teef reh gnicalp yb enod d'yeht krow eht fo egatnavda koot eaM dna
".aksiK htiw kcab edir a hctih neht dna ,eceip ruoy mih llet
sih ot ni llac a edam d’yeht dna
.sega ekat ot demees tI
.nwod mih tes eaM tnemom a retfA
”sthgileD nrehtroN“
,gab gnipeels reh no nwod deppolp dna dehgis eaM ".tniopkcehc
.teef sih yb gniyl ylsuoiverp deciton t'ndah leafaR hcihw
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.meht fo daeha liart eht hctaw pleh ot sa llew sa
"?naem uoy od tahW" .desum aksiK
.gnitnap dna kcab sih ot revo gnippolf ,dias eh ",evila m'I"
.hcra eht ot resolc esoht morf pu tnew yrc A
,liart niam eht ffo erew yehT
.pu mraw ot tpmetta na ni
.auhauhihC a m'I dnA" .dednopser leafaR ",edir a dehctiH"
.otsug htiw ssik eht denruter leafaR
.noitavresbo rof thginrevo latipsoh eht ni tpek saw leafaR
.liart eht ffo tuc d'yeht erehw edam d'yeht skram eht tuo ekam tsuj dluoc leafaR
.mih no gnidnuop erew dna dednuorrus ieW gnaW dah kcap sih dna margnI .hsurbrednu
dranreB tniaS lacidem eht htiw elbuod gnidir ,aksiK
.aksiK ot klat ot kcab tnew leafaR ,tnet reh pu kcab dekcap eaM elihW ".ecnarudne
.reh rednu enorp gniyl margnI ot kcab noitnetta reh denrut dna daeh reh koohs ehS ".ssim
.aksalA fo etats eht ni noisivelet yreve no gniyalp eb ot demees ecar eht taht derevocsid d'eh sa od ot ysae
.decamirg leafaR ".gninnur
.ytiradilos fo tnemom a gnirahs
.leafaR ot kcab noitnetta reh gninrut erofeb tnemom gnol a rof wollip reh ta ylgnignol gnikool
.gab sih fo tekcop edis eht fo tuo rennab sih dellup dna sehcturc sih detnalp eH
.redluohs eno revo gnuls kcap reh ,meht ot revo
.ti fo erus m'I ,seiksuh eht fo enO"
.dekrab ieW gnaW "!arierreF evitceteD"
.melborp elttil htiw emoN ni enalp eht ffo sriats eht dednecsed ylisae dna
,srennur denosaes era kcap sih dna margnI
,srekrow-oc ym fo wef a
.recar wen a pleh ot gnihtyna od ylgnilliw reven d'eH
.noitasucca s'leafaR hguorht gnikniht ylsuoivbo
.aksalA ni gniyats m'I"
.noitatirri ni ffo noisivelet eht deppilf leafaR
,srennur eseht ni kcehc og ot deen I"
.daeh s'eaM fo kcab eht dnuora ees ot edis eht ot denael leafaR ".ti
.tuo mih gnillup
.gel s'margnI htiw detcennoc swap tnorf gnilialf s'leafaR
.noonretfa siht yb latipsoh eht fo tuo eb ll'uoy em llet yehT"
.reh tsniaga delggurts eh sa kcab delworg margnI ",yenom eht dedeen dna ekorb saw I gnikniht saw I"
.esle gnihtyna yas dluoc ssob sih erofeb enohp eht pu gnuh eH ".aksalA
noonretfa taht raelc lla eht mih evag srotcod eht nehW
.gnisaet dna ,wols ,suousnes
--- anozirA ni rosivrepus
.sgnul sih denrub ria psirc dloc ehT
.uoy llet em tel ,soahc fo tib a saw ti dna
.elims derit a ieW gnaW evag dna daeh sih denrut leafaR ".tnemetatsrednu
.sgod ecilop lacol fo gnirts a htiw gnola pu deraor
.desaerc dna delpmur ti tfel dah kcapkcab s'eaM ni pirt siH
,emankcin a yb dellac gnieb detah eH
.spohc sih dekcil leafaR ".xineohP
,wons eht hguorht htap a dedrof dah sgod rehto ehT
.elbidercni saw niap eht tub
.nwad fo hsulb knip lauteprep a yks eht evag hcihw ,noziroh eht evoba hcum esor reven nus ehT
.taoc dna tah sih denethgiarts neht dna flesmih koohs leafaR
.pirg sih fo tuo nori erit eht eltserw ot gniyrt nageb eno rehto reh htiw dna
,hcrA delruB eht dnuora dworc eht nioj ot revo delbboh leafaR
.gninnur emit eraps ym lla tneps I ecnis
"?ereht kcab deneppah tahW
.enog saw ti litnu gniyrrac neeb d'eh dezilaer t'ndah eh nedrub a ,sredluohs sih morf detfil thgiew A
.ecaf sih fo tnorf ni ti gnidloh ,rehgih erutcip eht desiar leafaR ".emoh mraw ,ecin ym ot kcab teg nac I renoos eht ,god siht dnif I retsaf eht dna ,seY" .dettut aksiK ".emoh
.eciov s'ieW gnaW ni sknaht dna feiler eht raeh ot mih dewolla god gib eht htiw ecnatniauqca gnol s'leafaR ylnO
.eaM tfel d'eh erehw ot kcab delffuhs dna denrut leafaR
.dniheb morf meht no decnuop
.stnap reh ffo wons gnihsurb
".setirovaf ym fo eno s’tI"
eb d'eh ,tuo ti tog eh ecnO
.gnihtemos no daeh ruoy tih evah tsum uoy yas d'I"
.srettel der gib ni emocleW daer tI
tekcop s'margnI ni 22. deretsigernu na dnuof dna sgod eht dehcraes yeht nehw niaga demrifnoc saw yrots s'leafaR
.syad owt tsal eht fo yenruoj rieht dna eaM fo thguoht eH
dloc dna sevolg railimafnu eht
,detnioppasid tsomla dekool ehs nrows evah dluow eh dna mih ta deknilb eaM ”.hO"
.puorg emit ruoy morf ni kcehc ot god hthgie eht er'uoY"
.eutats sutcac eht ot txen ,sreh ni wap a decalp dna revo dehcaer leafaR
.ffo mih tuc eaM tub ,ecalp otni kcab dils eh sa nageb leafaR "--I ,eaM"
,ylwols os did ehs yawa dellup ehs nehW
2 fo 2 traP ,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.noitnetta reh teg ot yletilop dekrab eh "?aksiK ,em esucxE"
”sthgileD nrehtroN“   yojne esaelP
.reh dniheb gnola gnirednulb tnahpele na ekil tlef leafaR .tsohg a ekil
.ti fo erus m'I ,margnI s'tahT"
?thgirla eh si ,ieW gnaW"
.pu ti dellor dna nwod ti nekat d'ehs ecno saw tnet reh
.won ydotsuc evitcetorp ni s'eH
reisae eaM ot klat dluoc eh os kcap eht ni dnuora detsiwt leafaR sruoh lareves retfA
,swen eht ni ssergorp s'rennur eht gniwollof ylregae keew eht tneps d'eH
.reh ta delworg margnI
.tserof siht ni eaM esol erad t'ndid eH
.hsurbrednu eht otni kcab ffo gnireev erofeb stnemom lareves rof meht fo tnorf ni gnola deppoh dna sehsub eht fo tuo ekorb wons eht no spets s'eaM yb deltrats tibbar A
.wap a tuo dleh eaM ".ereh
ieW gnaW ot gniod erew yeht tahw ni devlovni oot erew kcap sih dna margnI demees ti yllufknahT
,pmulc a ni devirra lla yehT"
",margnI ,ekatsim gib a gnikam morf uoy gnippotS"
".tniopkcehc ekaL regniF eht ta pirtsria oN
.ecnarudne tuoba s'tI"
.ekirts ot ydaer ,daeh sih evoba ti detfil margnI
",gnihctaw s'eno on ,yrrow t'noD"
derekcilf srae dna ecaf reH
.taoc reh fo tuo gnilggirw ,dias eaM ”?noitseuq ruoy s’tahw oS“
tegrat rieht ot meht gnitaeb no degnih nalp elohw sih tub ,ieW gnaW retfa erew snissassa nwonk d'eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,dedeen eh tahw reh ot gninialpxe enod saw eh emit eht yB
.nekorb ylniatrec tsomlA
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,daehrevo deltsihw nori erit ehT
.swap htob ni deppirg nug eralf s'eaM gniyrrac saw eH
--- ti rof pleh on saw ereht tub ecniw leafaR edam taht
.wodaem eht dnoyeb seert eht otni deraeppasid yeht ,dehctaw yeht sa nevE
.fo erac nekat setam kcap s'margnI dah ieW gnaW ekil dekool ti
stsif sa sdnuos eht retsiger ot tnemom a leafaR koot tI
orp a ekil sehcturc eht no dnuora gnitteg saw eh keew eht fo dne eht yB
,arierreF tnanetueiL"
.yllanif dias leafaR
.ylecreif kcab eaM degguh eH
.toob ot ssem eht otni snailivic deggard d'eh dna
.og ot denrut eH ".sknahT"
teef sih depmots dna delworg leafaR ".puorg
,slap owt s'margnI dah ieW gnaW
a gnidnes hcnarb gnignah-wol a rednu dekcud eaM
.yliratnulovni gaw liat sih edam reh fo tnecs eht dna
.enigne eht fo elbmur eht revo delley eh "!eaM"
,efil s'mitciv eht gnivas htiw evitceted nwot-fo-tuo na fo gnikniht kciuq eht desiarp yehT
,dworc eht fo tser eht ot thgieh tsehc tnaem
.eybdoog gniyas tuohtiw tfel yeht ,hO"
,hguorht semoc eh litnu ereh tuo gnah si od ot evah ll'uoy lla neht dnA"
"?mih tuoba uoy deksa esle ohw ksa I nac ,mU .t'ndid I"
.edisni delwarc leafaR dna dnuorg eht no gab eht tup eaM
.ygolopa ruoy tpecca I"
,recar emit-tsrif a taht tespu tsuj ylbaborp saw eh kniht I
.reehc ot tuo emoc dah sgod fo sderdnuh ,swen eht no nees d'eh tahw morf dna ,yadretsey ni emoc dah srehto evif htiw gnola renniw ehT
.nwad dna ,ekoms doow
.cidem eht htiw noitasrevnoc detamina ni degagne won erew ohw ,sgod wen eht teerg ot ffo dednuob dna noitcafsitas ni daeh reh debbob aksiK
,gnilrans ,leafaR ecaf ot delrihw margnI
egdab sih meht gniwohs yldetaeper retfa ,yllautneve tuB
.did ehs sa kcil a eson sih fo pit eht gnivig
,ydaerla ereh hguorht emoc sah ieW
.srae s'leafaR gnilffur ezeerb llihc eht ,meht dnuora delriws wonS
,nug eralf eht detfil ,htaerb gib a koot leafaR
.reh ot pu hctac ot elba saw eh emit eht yb sgod fo gnirehtag eht dehcaer d'ehs taht tnaem sedirts gnol reH
,taoc knip sih fo kcab eht yb mih debbarg dna wap a ni dehcaer ehS
.eaM deksa god rehto eht
"!ecalp htneveS .hsinif gib eht no snoitalutargnoC" ".tcefrep s'tI"
.deddon dna redrah derevihs leafaR ".rehtaew
.neeb d'eh gnorw woh tuo dnuof eh won dna
.ti ees dluow eaM tnedifnoc saw eh tub
,pu demraw saw eh litnu elzzum sih ot kcap leg eht desserp dna taoc sih deppiznu eH
,rellams hcum saw yadot dworc ehT
,reh was leafaR tsal
".yawa em koot scidem eht nehw mih fo kcart tsol I
.erehwyna mrof taht ezingocer dluow leafaR
.noziroh eht raen seert eht otni gniraeppasid ,ecnatsid eht otni yawa dekans liart A
gnaW fI .srotanidrooc ecar eht fo eno s'ehS"
"?ezis ruoy fo esuaceB"
.era uoy won fo sA"
daeh s'leafaR dekrej evom ehT
.nees gnieb fo suoicsnoc ylneddus ,thgis fo tuo kcab dekcud leafaR
.regnad eht fo mih gninraw dna
,derebmuntuo dna derujni saw eh taht tcaf eht etipseD
.mih dessim tsuj uoY"
.sgod fo puorg a doots ecnatsid eht ni raF
.ysmulc swap suoretxed yllamron sih gnikam
.setumalam dna seiksuh erew dworc eht fo tser ehT
.yltneloiv derevihs leafaR
.seert eht deraen yeht sa derepsihw eh ",yrruH"
rethgual suotoir otni tsrub seiksuh eht fo enO
.god doog a gnieb mih sdrawot detniop margnI tuoba dias dah eaM taht gnihtoN
.oga ruoh na tuoba ereh tog eH
.srettel kcolb ,gib ni
.sruof lla ot deppord dna edis eht ot detrad leafaR
.deeps cinosrepus ta liat sih gniggaw dna daeh sih evoba tuoba
,reh dlot leafaR ",og ot ydaer m'I"
,pukcab ro noissimrep tuohtiw noitcidsiruj sih fo tuo ,aksalA ot ffo gnirah enog d'eh ,lla retfA
.kcab delbmarcs dna nug ytpme won eht deppord leafaR "!pots dias I"
.airohpue yzah fo duolc a ni mih deyoub hcihw ,niap eht rof sgurd eht yb gnola depleh saw eH
,regnol ereht neeb dah taht sgod regral fo tol a revo evitceted ot detomorp saw I nehW
.ecar tsrif sih si ti esuaceb ieW gnaW no kcehc ot detnaw eH .god ecin a hcuS
".pu tes tnet ym evah dluohs I kcab teg uoy emit eht yb dna aksiK ot klat og dna yrruH .dloc kool uoY"
.sehcni erem yb daeh s'leafaR gnissim
.ecnatsissa s'eaM fo noitnem on evag tub
.ieW gnaW retfa snissassa eht eb thgim seiddub sih dna margnI diarfa m'I"
.tfos yltnasaelp dekool dna etihw wons saw htaenrednu ruf ehT
.gninepo dereppiz eht hguorht gniraeppasid tsuj saw liat ylruc s'eaM dna
.deilper god railimafnu na ",dab oot toN"
.gnivom deppots enoyreve dna pu deppans daeh s'margnI
.htaerb gnissih a ni werd leafaR
.ti htiw og ot sunob ecin a flesruoy denrae dna tnanetueiL edam tsuj uoY
.ylsuoiruf deggaw liat reh dna nepo depag elzzum reH
,sgod tew fo dellems ria ehT
.sehctap eht fo sroloc dna tnemecalp eht ezingocer I
.recar rehtona fo redrum detpmetta eht htiw degrahc
.enil gnitrats eht ta kcab mih dekcirt dah taht god eht sa mih dezingocer yldetaleb leafaR dna
.ssim t'ndid I" .deilper tsuj eh daetsni oS
.sehtolc eraps reh otni nwod gnilgguns ,dias leafaR ",ecivda ruoy fo emos koot I"
,niaga nwod depmots margnI litnu detiaw eH
.puorg taht fo eno ,yawynA
.tif evah t'ndluow eh ,reggib yna neeb dah leafaR fI
.nirg a mih dehsalf eaM ".gnihtemos
.god etihw eht retfa ffo koot neht ,dias leafaR ",sknahT"
.hcamots sih ni daerd fo tonk drah a tfel dah mih ta dam saw ehs taht tcaf eht dna eaM ekil ot nugeb dah eH
.seert eht otni ffo deggoj dna kcap reh tfel eaM
.kcab dekcoc hcae rae eno dna
,mra s'margnI dnuora wap a depparw ehS
.tfil a em evig ll'yeht deen eht meht ot nialpxe I fi erus m'I
.noziroh tnatsid eht detanimod sniatnuom deppac-wons ecnatsid eht nI
.rehtaew siht rof ylreporp desserd ton er'uoY
.derif saw eh nehw od ot tahw rof snalp gnikam neeb d'eh thgin tsaL
".tsenif ruo fo maet a yb kcolc eht dnuor dedrauG
.etihw fo staoc ni seert eht depard wonS
.gnorw eb ot dah eh ,on tub
,peels dedeen eh taht snoitatsetorp sesrun eht revO
"?rennur retsaf eht s'ieW gnaW fi ,woH"
.ylsuoiruc detlit daeh reh ,mih ot txen nwod dehcuorc eaM
".stnuoc tahw s'taht ,ieW gnaW devas eW"
.sehcturc sih esu ot elbanu
.erofeb lufituaeb sa wons fo thguoht reven d'eH
.daeh sih dekcud dna wons eht otni toob sih fo eot eht gud leafaR ".hO"
,ieW gnaW no kcatta rieht ffo gnivael ,mih ecaf ot denrut seiddub kcap owt siH
.ni kcab daeh sih dellup dna derevihs eH
?uoy era god fo dnik tahW"
.tseb eht rof ylbaborP
.erac t'ndid eh tub ,wons eht otno nwod gnirettalc tnew rennab sih dna sehcturc
,smoor letoh ,stekcit enalp gniredro enohp eht no gninrom eht fo tser eht tneps leafaR
.deggaw liat s'eaM ".ecnahc
.mih was ehs nehw tnemeticxe htiw deppiy eaM .dnuorg eht tsniaga tsrif-ecaf meht fo hcae gnidloh wap evissam eno
.ieW gnaW nraw ot emit ni ereht nettog evah yeht fi tuo dnif lliw leafaR erehw tniopkcehc eht gnihcaer ot esolc erew yehT
s'leafaR .guh thgit a otni pu leafaR depoocs dna reh teerg ot pu emoc dah ohw slaiciffo ecar eht tsap thgir nar ehS
"?yas uoy dluow tahw
.aksiK desserdda dna mih derongi yldetniop leafaR .margnI
.stnap dna sakrap erew ees dluoc eh lla tub ,pu ecnalg ot deirt eH
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.ecnahc eht tog uoy sa noos sa
.tnemetatsrednu na eb dluow uoy ees ot dekcohs m'I yas oT"
.deunitnoc eh ylknalb mih ta derats enoyreve nehW ".auhauhihC
.htaenrednu dessap ehs sa deraor dworc eht dna ,hcra eht ot sdray derdnuh tsal eht detnirps eaM
.selibomwons evah htob cidem eht dna aksiK .oN"
.krowhctap gnignahc reve na ni
.liart eht gnola gniggoj serugif tnatsid fo puorg a ot detniop dna denrut aksiK ",saw tI" .sevolg dna tah sih hguorht nwod peerc ot nageb dloc eht dna
.lworg peed a dna niap fo pley a emac tfel sih morF
".uoy tsniaga degnarra si enoyreve ekil sleef ti nehw eb nac ti drah woh dnatsrednu I"
.depoohw eaM "!leafaR"
sgod wen owt teerg ot ffo derednaw dranreB tniaS lacidem ehT
,snoitome fo yteirav a hguorht
.srennur eht rof dia tsrif
.yas eaM draehrevo eH "?sgnidnats eht ni I ma erehW"
.leafaR ot kcab ezag reh denrut neht ieW gnaW ta denworf eaM .meht evoba seert eht morf wons koohs taht
.wons fo reyal yci na ni derevoc dleif nepo na ni erew yehT
.der fo hsalf a ni seert eht evoba tsrub ot swap dehctertstuo s'leafaR morf pu tohs eralf ehT
"?no sserp ot gniog uoY"
.detniop dna wap a pu dleh ,deppots eaM .eciton ot
,paY margnI gnilrad ecar fo tserra esirprus eht tuoba saw egarevoc eht fo tol A
.mih ot gnillac saw ehs fi neve ,reh tsol eh fi eaM dnif ot elba eb d'eh erus t'nsaw eh dna
.wons eht no stoob reh fo hcnurc eht dna gnihtaerb hsrah s'eaM erew sdnuos ylno ehT
.ruf taht ot pu eldduc ot ekil eb d'ti tahw gnirednow flesmih thguac leafaR
deksanu sih ot esnopser ni dias eaM ",taoc siH"
,ton ro nekorb saw ti fi llet t'ndluoc eh ;debborht gel siH .margnI gnisaeler dna tuo gniyrc morf peek ot hteet sih tirg ot dah eh dna ,liat dna gel tfel s'leafaR no drah nwod emac toob ehT
.ereh uoy ees ot desirprus m'I .uoy knahT"
.etib-tsorf evah t'nod uoy erus ekam dna cidem eht ees og dluohs uoy tub
.pu gnisnet saw eh edisni tub
.mih ees t'ndluoc eaM dalg saw dna ruf trohs sih hguorht elbisiv neeb evah dluow gnihsulb sh wenk eH
,dnuos a ylerab htiw dessap eaM
.won rof kcapkcab sih ni
",gnorw meht evorp ll'I ,tsub gib siht teg dna ,tnamrofni ym evas nac I fi ,ekil leef I"
sutcac cimarec elttil eht ta nwod dekool ehs sa htrim htiw gninihs seye ,swap reh htiw elzzum reh derevoc dna dehgual eaM .hsiruolf elttil a htiw ti detneserp dna eutats eht tuo dellup eH ".uoy roF"
.ecar eht fo swen wohs ot noisivelet eht no nrut meht edam leafaR
,otohp s'ieW gnaW pu dleh dna deliaverp eh yllaniF
.skcapkcab rieht pu derehtag setumalam dna seiksuh eht ,trapa ekorb sgod fo puorg eht meht dnuorA
.lufthgiled erom gnihtyna dellems reven d'eH .trid dna ,seert
.omiksE naciremA gnitaerter eht sdrawot daeh
.dehgis leafaR ".ecrof eht no sauhauhihC rehto era erehT"
.ecnalab ffo mih gnivael ,yawa dellup wap reH "!daeha pu ,erehT"
.kcab delworg eaM
.ti fo tuo saw eh litnu mih gnillihc neeb dah ezeerb thgils eht hcum woh tsuj dezilaer t'ndah leafaR .edistuo naht remraw yltnacifingis saw tnet eht edisni ydaerlA
.thgin tsal dias I tahw esucxe t'ndid ti tub ,dloc dna ,deifirret m'I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sgel sih neewteb liat sih dekcut dna derevihs leafaR
.deneppah dah tahw deyaler dna decamirg leafaR ".fo
.nwod mih tas ehs sa mih ot derepsihw eaM
.ieW gnaW evas dluoc eh erofeb egarohcnA ot kcab tnes ylbicrof eb ot ro ,elbuort ni eaM teg ot ereh ecneserp sih tnaw t'ndid eH
.reh dniheb pu emac leafaR nehw meht htiw noitasrevnoc ni ydaerla saw ehS
,thgit gnignilc ,swalc sih ni gud eH
.tnelis llef leafaR ".taht
,htaenrednu deppart saw leafaR
"?yllacificeps ,eno hcihW"
nesir dah ieW gnaW taht ees ot noitcerid taht decnalg dna ecnahc a koot leafaR
,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.rettil fael dna ,wons ,ruf fo elbmuj gnillaf a otni denrut weivdlrow s'leafaR dna delwoh god gib ehT
.laog rieht dna mih neewteb
.hself htiw gnitcennoc
.htaerb peed a koot leafaR "...I
,swap tnorf sih htiw toob s'margnI ta dewalc eH
.eson sih delknirw leafaR
,regral ylidaets werg tod gninnur ehT
.yawa deggoj ehs sa tuo deffuh eaM "?tuoba taht saw tahW" "!kcul doog ,eaM"
liart gnidnuorrus eht til dna wons debrutsidnu eht no derettilg nus ehT
,skooB goD wobniaR dehsilbup
.gninepo eht htiw gnilbmuf eaM draeh eh neht dna pmuht a htiw dnuorg eht tih kcapkcab ehT
.yoj htiw delkraps seye reh dna elzzum reh tilps nirg egral a tub
keeW krahS detide dna
.uoy sserpmi ot redro ni ,ma I naht delevart erom dnuos ot detnaw I"
.ydaerla enog dna emoc sah ieW gnaW
,dias leafaR ",meht fo ecin s'taht ,hO"
.mih sdrawot degrahc margnI tcaer dluoc leafaR erofeB
.enil eert eht ta tsomla
.tuoba nups eh sa wons eht no dehcnurc stoob siH
",eunitnoc I erofeb peels fo sruoh wef a deen I .tey toN"
nehw dah ehs naht renniht dekool ehS
"?ereh tuo yaw eht lla teg uoy did woh dnA ?god a uoy erA
,ti depsarg leafaR .redluohs reh revo kcab dehcaer swap s'eaM fo enO
.srosnops etaroproc sah dna sraey rof ecar eht gniod neeb sah margnI" .noitseuq
.yrassecen ton s'taht ,riS"
.ssentiw s'etats nrut ot deerga sah ieW gnaW ,uoy ot sknahT
".noitseuq a uoy ksa ot dna eybdoog yas ot kcab emac tsuj I
,noitanitsed tsrif sih ot
"?esidarap evael ot tnaw I dluow yhW"
.tekcop sih otni kcab otohp s'ieW gnaW deffuts dna desruc leafaR
,htaerb peed a koot eH ".yrassecen
rennab eht gnivaw rof delttes eh daetsnI
.rennab dednepsus a fo selop eht ot txen pu denil erew selibomwons owT
.nirg dehtuom-nepo hsipeehs a htiw sehcturc sih deveirter eaM
!margnI saw ti ,sey ,hO .oN ?einreB ti saW
.taht naht nug a htiw tohs retteb a erew uoy thguoht I ,eiffaR"
.feiler ni htaerb a tuo welb leafaR ".drol eht knahT"
.rehtaf reh ekil rennur a eb ot erised reh decnuonna d'ehs nehw dah d'ehs thgif eht dna
.dloc gnitteg ydaerla saw eh dna setunim wef a rof kcapkcab s'eaM fo tuo neeb ylno d'eH
tuoba dezag eh sa ,revewoH .citamorhconom tsomla dna kaelb mih ot demees dah sepacsdnal ywons fo nees d'eh serutciP
.rennab eht pu gnidloh elop raf eht ot txen detagergnoc sgod wef A
elihw tsac sih no thgiew tup ot ton tseb sih gniod ,gel eno no ylsuoiracerp decnalab leafaR
.yawa dellup yeht sa ecaf reh hctaw ot detsiwt leafaR
...I .thgin tsal tuoba yrros m'I"
.eaM ot gniteerg a gnikrab god rehtona yb nekow saw leafaR
.gnikahs erew swap sih gnizilaer
"?thgirla uoy erA"
reh gnibbob ,dias eaM ",wohC ruoy tuoba aksiK ot klat d'I" .srettel wolley gib ni reetnulov daer tekcaj reh fo kcab ehT .sgod fo tonk eht sdrawot dedaeh ,eaM dna mih morf yawa gniklaw saw
.tnirps a neht dna ,goj a otni gninrut epol reh ,pu deps eaM ".sehctap
.toof sih detfil margnI sa derevaw noisiv siH
.keehc s'eaM dekcil dna ,redluohs s'eaM revo ,drawrof denael leafaR
.derettit dworc ehT
,hsinif ot tes saw eaM nehw yltcaxe erus t'nsaw eH
.ti tnaem dna ,dias eh ",yrros m'I"
kcalb ni nam eht ot mih ecudortnI
.detniuqs dna drawrof denael leafaR
nettirw saw hcihw fo kcab eht no
.daeh sih koohs leafaR
.tniopkcehc eht ta gnivirra
.fo diarfa saw I tahw s'tahT" "?yhW
.mih deyarteb srae sih wenk eh tub ,hsulb sih edih ot deirt dna dennirg leafaR
.foow a htiw ffo mih tuc niatpaC ehT "-
.os kniht t'nod I ,oN" .retaw ffo gnikahs fi sa flesreh koohs ehs yllaniF
,noitats antnewkS morf
.tsehc sih tsniaga kcab kcap eht dekcut neht
,erofeb ecap eht gnihsup neeb dah eaM thguoht leafaR