”.nwod siht evil em tel reven dluow aniraS
,tnemom a rof dengier ecneliS
— emot kciht a werdhtiw eh ebor sih ni tils a nihtiw morF
.ydob dekan sih etacidni ot fi sa nwod dekcilf seye siH
.moor mrod degnahc rieht dnuora dekool eh sa
”.noihsaf a retfa ,noisnecsa deveihca ylniatrec I“
”.ytiuteprep detciped uoY
”!anacra fo esusim rof tuo em worht ll’ehS“
”.enod lleW .yllaeR .desserpmi m’I ,oN“
.sucof sih peek ot thguof eh sa pu ezorf yeliR dna
-selcric cinur ssorca detfird
?od ot em tcepxe uoy od tahw neht ,retsamdaeh eht hctef ot ton m’I fi lleW“
”.sesimorp ,sesimorP“ ”.noitubirtnoc
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.uoy htiw erahs won I taht ecnatsmucric eht yb tnedive
”?yas uoy t’ndluow ,tnemom eht rovas naht rehto gnihtyna od ot evitnecni hcum yllaer toN .ytniatrec a sA“
thgil etihw-eulb tfos a htiw wolg ot nageb walc sih fo pit eht dna
…erom …tib …elttil a
gniliec eht ot dennip selam eht ta pu derats ehS
.deksa anireS ”?lleW“ ”.sknaht ,ti toG“
tcejbo eht otni demmals eH
,ecaf s’enialB ssorc ot demees noitatirri s’tnemom A
.noinapmoc latnedicca sih drawot daeh sih fo nrut eht saw wols os
.mmM“ ”.esoppus I ,doog ooT“
.denediw seye s’enialB ”.ytiutepreP“
”.rof gnikool erew uoy tahw s’ti tsael tA“
.mrofienuc narucrA desu evah t’ndluohs uoY .tniop riaF“ ”.ereh
”.ti wonk I t’noD“
.detapicitna d’eh naht ydob sih ni rewol etiuq dna
.ti htiw od ot gnihtemos dah evah yam
daeh sih dekcoc yeliR sa niaga dehguoc eH
.swap sih ni daeh sih dah evah dluow flow eht
.daeh sih gnikahs ylsuorogiv enialB ees ot pu kcab dekool eh dna
rehtie era shpargotcip eht ,gnirujnoc ni desU
.liava elttil yllauqe ot saw ti tub
.edis ot edis morf waj sih dekrow xof ehT
.htap sih ni pu deppihw saw rulb yarg a litnu mih drawot pu decar evah dluow roolf ehT
”.sbmil motnahp emos erujnoc ot deirt I oS“
,sllaw yddur eht ssorca dekar tI
”?mrofienuc narucrA ni segnahc eht gnizilausiv uoy ereW“ ”.enialB“
naem osla nac tI“ .deddon xof ehT
.evitcepsrep ruoy morF“ ”.melborp
.dehgis enialB sa delims eh dna
”.enola ereh saw I nehw naht elbatrofmoc erom hcum si sihT ?I tsuM“
”?diputs gnileeF“ ”.seY“ ”?cinocarD“ ”.hO“
.decamirg yeliR ”.ho …saw I ,oN“
,kcab srae dna deworran seyE
— elttil evah uoy hcihw fo — lleps eht fo txetnoc eht yb nevird
.noitubirtnoc fo tros tnereffid a gniviecer flesruoy dnif llew thgim uoy dna taht ekil
’,selppa‘ naem osla nac ti elihw dnA“
”.traeh ym lla htiW .yllacoviuqenU .ylhguorohT“
.srae sih krep ot yeliR desuac drow ehT ”.tihs …llew ,seY“
.lobmys suoenorre eht ssorca yltneg regnif a decart yeliR
.derettilg seye ’ssenoil ehT
.elcric eht ot resolc denael eh sa drawrof deppit srae sih
”.enod evah dluoc I senur desu d’uoy fi ebyaM“
”.wonk I“ ”.uoy etah I“
,lliw ,ygrene fo noitacilppa reporp eht htiw
”.rorre ni eb llew thgim taht etammoor demeetse ruo fo taht ot derapmoc roivaheb erutuf ym tuoba ereht noitpmussa lacitirc a ekam uoY“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.tnemetatsrednu na fo gnihtemos eb thgim ’deirt‘ yas oT“
.rood eht drawot detrats eh sa deggurhs yeliR
.yltcerroc ecneulfni ot deliaf d’eh slobmys mrofienuc fo elcric eht ta derats eh sa dna
”.ecrof fo noitacilppa tcerroc eht htiw niks ecreip nac gnihtynA
”.etarobalE .tuo derugif siht dah uoy dias uoY .eniF“
elcric tseraen eht ot revo dehcram xof ehT
.tiaW“ .ediskcab deppart s’yeliR tsniaga ylmrif erom flesmih gnidnirg pu dnuow ylno ti tub ,gurhs ot deirt evah thgim enialB
,deworruf worb s’yeliR ”.hsuH“
”.tuo uoy worht ll’ehS“
.dehgis yeliR sa nrut ni yltfos denaom flow eht dna ,hctorc s’enialB tsniaga kcab dnirg ot demees ylno ti daetsnI .deirt ro
”.yeliR ,niaga siht deen t’nod I“ ”.buc ynit A“
.dnoces taht rof llaf flesmih tlef eh sa
.niaga stniartser sih ni mriuqs ot nageb eH
.retsamdaeh oN .llew yreV“
gnilggirw peeK“ ”.deviecer llew si noitubirtnoc ruoY
”.cigam fo snoitacilppa lanrac erom ruoy rof senur cinocard esu ot swonk tneduts raey-dnoces a nevE“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.niaga rehtegot seidob rieht desserp ti yaw eht ni sredluohs s’flow eht fo gurhs eht tlef eH
”.roolf eht sdrager sa eussi na ylno s’ti ,lleW“
elims dedispol a mih werht xof ehT
.niaga elcric eht ta derats yeliR
.gniliec eht tsniaga kcab sih dnuorg enialB ,trap sih roF
”.siht ekil deniur edirp ym evah t’now I“ ”.ybab a era uoY“
.deilper flow eht
”.ton er’uoy oN“ ”.yrroS“
.niaga spih sih fo dnirg elttil a deirt enialB sa dedda eh ”,on dnA .kcuF“
.delkcuhc flow ehT ”.won
.ti degnir taht slobmys eht fo eno deppat dna
”.ytiuteprep naem t’ndid I ylsuoivbO“
,serutseg enacra tcerroc eht ekam ro yllacisyhp
,neeb reve evah ereht taht sdog eht lla yb raews I ,enialB“
.seye sih desolc dna dehgis xof ehT ”.gnitiaw m’I“
”.elbat eht no llits si sixarikS ot tnemhsinab tahT
rioduob tileldnac a laever ot wap sih fo evaw a rednu yawa detlem rood moor mrod s’xof debor-yarg a nehw oS
”.emoclew etiuq er’uoy ,seY“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.deworran seye s’enialB
,tcatnoc esolc rieht hguorht taebtraeh s’flow eht leef ot elba ylneddus flesmih dnuof yeliR
.niaga spih sih dellor flow eht
.noitulos a rof elcric eht revo dekool eh sa
,tenalpruF dna flowafoS yb dehsilbup neeb evah seirots trohs esohw retirw yrruf emitgnol a
.dehguoc flow ehT .deknilb xof ehT
denworf yeliR ”.ton er’uoy oN“
”.yad lla gnikconk ereht eb d’uoY“
.stniartser sih ni gniggas fo tca eht rof elttes ot dah eh
”.uoy knaht ,ti tog I“
knip werg srae s’flow eht fo sedisni ehT
”!aedi ruoy saw ti reh llet ot erus ekam ll’I“
”.sdrow ym kraM .revo si siht nehw sixarikS fo sdleif ralop eht ot uoy hsinab lliw I“
?selppA“ .pu dekrep dna
”.ton esoppus I ,oN“
,anireS“ .yawa decnalg eh sa dehgis enialB ”!eniF“
.tnemaciderp s’flow eht deredisnoc niaga ecno yeliR
”.noisserpmi taht uoy sevig tahw llet yarP“
”.sterref dellac tsuj er’yeht kniht I“ ”.terref ynnikS“
”.reh revo ’thgim‘ ekat ll’I ,won thgiR“
noihsaf enilucsamnu yltcnitsid a ni deppiy flow eht dna
.niaga wap sih devaw yeliR ”.tniop riaF“
.htaerb rof stnap s’yeliR yb detautcnup
”.niw dluow I .dooG“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.niaga weiv otni xof eht dna elcric eht gnirb ot hguone tsuj daeh sih enarc ot stnemom wef a koot tI
…neeb atros ev’eW
niaga flesmih ot demmuh yeliR
”-llew …em fo aedi eht dekil eh dnA“
…dekcut liat s’yeliR
.flesti tigid eht sa wolg emas eht no ekat ot nageb regnif s’yeliR rednu lobmys ehT
,dedaf ylurt dna llew dah wolg ehT
”.pu dekcuf uoy nehT“ ”.ylsuoivbo ,lleW“
,dias eh ”,eveileb I“
.wolg enacra ,lanretni
er’uoY“ ”!ekatsim siht ekam ot sa diputs os eb dluow I taht eveileb reven dluow ehS“
”?uoy t’nera ,ssenkrad eht ni ylteiuq gnilweM“
.yrros m’I“ ”?ylsuoireS
.eugaelloc gnurts-gniliec sih dedrager dna smra sih dedlof eh sa
.dnim on ti diap eh
.daeh sih dekcoc enialB
.dekcut saw liat sih hguoht ,neve
.tsael ta ,hcterts a s’ti ekil skool ti rO“
”!tuo su worht ll’ehs ,oN“
.kcals llaf ot flesmih dewolla eh erofeb tnemom a rof niaga delggurts flow ehT
os tnemtnahcne animats rof kcank a htiw terref mils a yb degavar gnieb ydob ym no ni klaw t’ndid uoY“
,elba neeb dah enialB fi taht niatrec saw yeliR
,flow dednepsus eht ffo draw ot swap htob detfil xof ehT
”.slliks tnenimeerp ruoy dna uoy rof sdeelb traeh yM
.dnuora flesmih tsiwt ot deirt eh sa denaorg flow ehT ”?gninaeM“
.dehguoc enialB ,mih dniheB
.yls denrut elims s’xof ehT
.moor eht dnuora dekool dna smra reh dedlof ssenoil eht sa ecaf s’anireS morf elttil a deppils elims ehT
”.melborp eno si roolf ehT“
”llA tI evobA oS toN“:yojne esaelP
,mih htiw dexaler sbmil sih dnuora slirdnet ehT .xaler oT
.pu dekcirp rae rehto s’yeliR
.niaga seye sih denepo eh sa dehgis eH
.kcab sih hcterts ot dehcra dna
.gniliec eht ot tsrif-kcab dehsal flow dekan eht no delttes dna-
”?ereh morf nwod su pleh esaelp uoy dluow
ot nageb lobmys mrofienuc eht nihtiw dialni wolg ehT
,ytiuteprep rof erised eht yb detimil ,tniartser ,tnemecrofnE ?ereh eeS
,niaga ecno lobmys eht nwod kcab nar
”.noituloser siht htiw smelborp owt ees I“ .decniw enialB
.noitom eht deterpretnisim evah tsum enialB tub ,weiv otni kcab elcric eht gnirb ot daeh sih detlit yeliR
.dehgis yeliR sa neve daeh sih koohs ylsuorogiv flow ehT
.etammoor regral sih hctac ylidob ot pu detfil dna roolf eht ecaf ot
”…ll’ehs dna retsamdaeh eht nommus uoY“
.sllaw sti nihtiw toof deppets uoy nehw rettam t’ndid noitaerc fo tser ehT
.yeliR“ .tnemesuma dna
,pu dekcuf ylraelc I ,seY“
,naidireM aroaF yb ”llA tI evobA oS toN“ saw sihT
,emahs ot dnal eht ni slehtorb tnagele tsom eht tup dluow taht
”.elat eht daerps ot tfel evah yam eh taht“
.rood eht drawot devaw yeliR
.ereh em tup tahw si taht yfitcer ot tpmetta yM
”-I tahw t’nsi tahT“
”.elppa na uoy no evah ot neppah dluow uoy“
”.nwod uoy tuc yltcaxe t’nac I
.ot detcepxe ylbaborp eh naht yltneg erom hcum
”.dedeeccus uoy yaserad I
tuoba nups saw eh sa regnif sih dna elcric eht morf dehsinav wolg ehT
,sisahpme rof derobaleb elballys yreve
”?yltneserp emalb ngissa ot deen ew oD
.mih rednu xof eht denefaed yllaitrap ti dna
”?sgniht ytniop eht lla ylnO“
,anireS ta tub erehwyna dekool eh sa delward eh ”,esoppus t’nod I“
ti hcuot ot ytiliba eht tuohtiw dna
,kcen s’xof eht fo kcab eht tsniaga elzzun ot ni devom flow ehT
”.kcuts ylhguoroht er’uoy …halb halb halb eht yb dekovni
,revewoh ecaf sih morf htgnel s’mra na ta tpek yleruces erew swap sih sA
”.nac I kniht I .sey neht
”.esicerpmi yllufdaerD
noitazilivic narucrA eht fo emit eht ot kcab flesym esopsnart yllaropmet I referp uoy dluoW
”.pu tuhs woN .cinorom ylevitisoP“
dellor seye s’enialB
taorht sih deraelc enialB
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.elzzum sih dnuora dekcil eh sa dedaf ti tub
”.os od thgim eh taht os reddal pets a nwod tnuh spahrep rO“
”.noitarujnoc htiw doog m’I llew ,seY“
”.neht ,deniatnoc ylefaS“ ”.gnipleh t’nera uoY“
.hteet sih tirg yeliR
dehctiwt srae s’enialB fo enO
”!oN“ ”-taht noitulos a evah ll’ehS .retsamdaeh eht hctef og ll’I“
.ton yllautca m’I“ ”.dekcuf
.yrrufoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”?nyvrO rebmemer uoy ,thgirlA .yakO“
”llA tI evobA oS toN“
”?llew sa taht eveihca uoy did dnA“
”.krow t’ndid taht woh dnatsrednu t’nod I .dekrow evah dluohs tahT“
.rae na dekrep eh sa worb
yeliR desirprus dna desufnoc a saw tcejbo eht tahT
”.on gniyas potS“ ”!oN .oN .oooooN .oN“
”.hcterts a s’tahT .haeY“
”,tluaf ruoy si sihT“
,seye sih desolc yeliR
.ydob s’flow eht dnuob taht slirdnet kciht eht dedrager eh sa
,elzzum sih nepo neve dluoc yeliR erofeb emac tuohs s’enialB
,moor mrod deretla eht ot rood denepo ylhserf eht edisni tsuj dna ,elameF
flesmih ot deddon yeliR
s’yeliR ”?flesruoy ot lla noitalever siht peek rehtar uoy dluow ro su fo tser eht nethgilne ot gnilliw uoy era dnA“
.taebtraeh sih htiw eslup
,meht dehctaw anireS sa ereht gnuh tI
”?ycaretil fo metsys reraelc a etaerc ot yletilop meht ksa dna
.rehtegot hteet sih tirg eh sa
.nihc sih ta debbur eh sa mih ot tseraen elcric eht no dexif seye s’xof ehT
”?uoy ot siht did eH“
”.yaw eht ni era sebor eht esuaceb taht gniyas tsuj er’uoY“ ”.esaelp
.niaga flow eht ta pu dekool eh sa desuap yeliR ”.noisnecsa sa
.seye reh dellor dna dehgis ehS
”.ereh noitpo na s’ereht ebyaM .ebyaM
noitazilausiv latnem-onacra lanretni na hguorht tnetni gnikovni uoy ereW
,enialB hcaer ot stnemom wef a koot eralg s’yeliR
detfihs dna depraw taht ytilaer a fo ecaf eht ni yawa detlem eb ot dootsrednu saw taht gnihtyrevE
os tnew lla siht woh tuo erugif ot deen eW
”?kniht seviw reh dluow tahW
”.rehto eht rof sekam ytivarg dna ,seY“
,yas yeht sa ,era uoY“
.mmH“ .lobmys suoenorre s’enialB ot noitcepsni sih fo sucof eht deworran eh sa
.esaelp uoy fi ,taht fo enoN .oN“
”.noisserpmoc laitaps fo esu citsatnaf hcus sekam cigam cinocard nosaer a
osla daer eb nac lobmys eht ,revewoH .ton ylsuoivbO“
denruter elims
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.redrah delggurts enialB
.flesti otnu dlrow a saw ymedaca cigam a taht d ootsrednu saw tI
.eye s’enialB thguac dna rehtruf elttil a daeh sih denrut yeliR
.htiw moor mrod rieht derevoc d’eh noisulli yduag revetahw
”.tnetni terces ruoy saw siht taht tbuod I
,mih evoba dna dniheB
,tsehc s’flow eht tsniaga desserp saw kcab gnimriuqs s’yeliR
.ediw tuo smra reh daerps ehS
;noitnetta rof deiv srewop elbirret dna taerG
.yrehpirep sih ni kool deifitrom s’enialB ees dluoc dna daeh sih denrut yeliR ”.anireS“ ”.enialB
.taht potS“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.elzzum s’flow eht fo tuo dils repmihw A
”.nwod uoy teg nac I kniht I dias I“ ”?niaga emoC“
.sgniht rehto pu denil osla noitisop taht tub
tsuj deen I .sucof ot deen I“
regnif s’xof ehT
”?tahw ,tiaw -ll’I erus m’I ,lleW“
.cinocarD hgiH desu evah dluohS“
.llits llef spih s’enialB ,sselehtreveN
”.flesym otni esnes emos kconk dluoc I os aedi doog a saw siht thguoht I nehw emit eht ot kcab flesym esopsnart yllaropmet uoy referp thgim I kniht I“
s’erehT“ ”.thgiR .hO“ ”.sdloboK“
.ytsedom s’yeliR tsael ta detcetorp llits sa sebor emas eht ni desserd saw ssenoil eht
.s’yeliR teem ot deliaf ylneddus seye sih sa
,elbat-dne depard-klis a no nwod ti tes
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,dnoces a rof dekcals gniliec eht ot enialB dnuob taht slirdnet ehT ”!ereht
.tneb eh sa esor ezag siH
.mih dednimer ylesret yeliR
.detimil saw noitautis sih tcerroc ot ytiliba sih
”?nwod gnitteg pleh emos deen uoy oD
”.gnimriuqs pots t’nac ohw eno eht er’uoY
.kcab deddon xof ehT ”.era yehT“
.tuo taht derugif ydaerla I llew ,seY“ ”.gnorw ylbirret
.tsum rehtar yllaer uoY“
”.ton did I taht sseug ot regaw dluow I
si yrots s’yadot dna
.erom ecno gniliec eht otni desserp erew yeht sa detnurg owt eht dna
.seripme pu esiar dna sgnik elppot dluoc taht rewoP .esrow ro
”?elcric eht nihtiw ecaps lacisyhpatem eht fo
”?hcaer sih fo tuO“ ”.oN“
.flesmih tcelloc ot xof eht rof tnemom a koot tI
naidireM aroaF yb
s’enipluv eht dehcuot nworf A
moor eht dnuora lla selcric eht nihtiw morf dednetxe slirdnet weN
”,siht fo lla rof noitanalpxe elbanosaer yrev a yllautca s’erehT“ ”.wen si sihT“
.srae sih denettalf eh sa deworran seye s’yeliR
”,siht rof noitanalpxe elbanosaer yrev a si yllaer erehT“
”!si ti revetahw ehT“ ”.mrofienuc ehT“
,sbmil s’enialB detcirtsnoc taht shtgnel kcalb yrebbur eht ot detfihs noitnetta s’xof ehT
selcric cinur elttil esoht fo retnec eht morf dedurtorp lla yeht dna ,gniliec eht dna llaw eht htob fo tuo emoc evah ot demees slirdnet ehT
ymedaca siht ni gniht ytniop elgnis yreve yllaretil htiw uoy bats ot yaw a dnif lliw I
.knilb dluoc eh naht retsaf sbmil s’xof eht tuoba delruc dah dna
.uoy s’ti dalg tsuj m’I“
”.epyt reh er’uoy kniht yldrah I“ .denworf yeliR
.tuo emac dnuos on tub ,ylper ot elzzum sih denepo yeliR
”.etiuq ,seY“ ”-ruoy daerps ot redro ni niamer ot derreferp evah dluow eh taht thguoht I“
?od ot em tcepxe uoy od tahW
,tnorf s’enialB tsniaga detfil saw eh sa ria eht hguorht pu deppihw sebor siH
.niaga mih tsniaga dnirg ot nageb flow eht sa neve
”?tnemaciderp ruoy was eh ecno ot ffo nur reggub elttil yknils eht d’erehW ?nyvrO dnA“
”.eergasid thgim I ,enim morF
,rae ot rae gninnirg llits
”.nrecnoc ym gnicrofnier suhT“
”.sgniht detsalb eseht erujnoc-nu ot serutseg tcerroc eht etaerc t’nac I won dnA“
,naidireM aroaF yb
.dekrims yeliR ”.tniop riaf A“
”.laog eht saw tahT“ ”.noitcafsitas
.spih sih delggirw eh sa niaga dehguoc enialB ”.haeY“ ”.hO“
.niaga ecno ediskcab s’yeliR tsniaga nwod flesmih dnuorg eh ,sisahpme roF
— noitamilbuS ciportnE fo noitacilppA esicerP eht dna eroL hctirdlE no esitaerT A
mih dniheb kcab devaw xof ehT
”?detavelE“ .dekrims yeliR
.tnelis deniamer eh hguoht
.eerf pils ot hguone ton tub
nialpxe t’nod uoy fi
.yeliR deye ehs sa elttil a detsiwt elims reH
.demrofer yltfiws moor eht ot rood eht dna
.reh dlot flow eht
,retsac dnoces a morf txetnoc
.daeh sih koohs eh sa flesmih ot demmuh yeliR ”.esaeleR“
.stcejbo tnulb ot wov eht dnetxe ll’I .pu ti peeK“
”.ti detcurtsnoc ev’I sa noos sa tsuj uoy ot ti evig ll’I …dnA“
.erugif a saw meht woleB ”-si tahw ,enialB“
.yrassecennu yleritne erew yeht tub ,sdrow ni rewsna t’ndid enialB ”?tihS“
.sbarg rof pu erew esrevinu eht denrevog taht selur ehT .egdelwonk dna
saw eciov siH
.epor ton saw roolf eht evoba teef lareves flow eht deppart taht egadnob ehT ”.yeliR“ ”.enialB“
.dnuob meht htiw dluoc eh tseb sa selcric ni swap sih dellor enialB ”.wonk uoy
,niaga elggurts ot nageb enialB
.dnim s’rerujnoc eht ni erised eht ro
”.ecnatsmucric tneserp ym evorpmi ot gnihton seod noitauqe siht ot stnemelpmi prahs gnicudortni uoy fo tcepsorp eht dna ,oN“
.denettalf srae s’enialB fo htoB
.gnorw eb tsum gnihtemos taht dezilaer yeliR litnu sdnoces erom wef a rof deunitnoc ecnelis tahT
.niaga desolc edils ot ti dewolla ylwols
.denediw nirg reh sa deilper ehs ”,yletulosba ,hO“
”.yrros fo tros m’I“
.ecneuqes ni elcric eht no slobmys eht ssorca regnif a decart eh sa elims ot nageb xof ehT ”.sey ,hO“ ”.oN“
!sediseb deirram dnA“ ”-I ,yeliR“
,tniop sih evorp ot fi sA
.tnemom a rof detcirtsnoc gel tfel s’enialB dnuora depparw dna elcric eht morf degreme dah taht lirdnet eht ,nrut nI
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
retteb rof dlrow eht egnahc ot rewop
.ecalp tsrif eht ni noitautis siht gnikovni pu dnuow ohw dos ydeen yletarepsed eht er’uoy dnA“
”?retnahcnesid raey-htxis emos dniF
.mlac ot flesmih decrof eH
”?noitarujnoc eht fo rotcaf gnitimil eht saw tahW“
”.drow rehtona toN“ ”.ylralucatceps rehtar deliaf tahT“ ”.oN“ ”.oS“
.melborp on si ytivarg ehT“
.lautxetnoc ylivaeh si mrofienuc narucrA“
”.eromyna drow a ekil dnuos neve t’nseod tI“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,skcart sih ni xof eht deppots tuohs ehT ”!oN“
lanoitidda htiw tnetni ruoy tnemgua nac I fI“ .detartnecnoc eh sa
”.enialB ,gnidnats hgih fo elamef denifer a s’ehS“
hguorht detsisrep wohemos taht
”?senur eht lepsid uoy naC“
,tnetni tnarre yb detullop saw lleps eht fo txetnoc eht fi ,seY .seY“
”.emit ruoy ekat ,hO“
.wap tnatcepxe na devaw dna
,dnoces a rof hctih ot demees htaerb s’flow ehT
”.mrofienuc narucrA si sihT“
,yllanif eh litnu
”.erehwyna gniog era su fo rehtie kniht t’nod I“
”.detaluclacsim evah yam I .os ,thgirlA“
”!em htiw ereh pu
”.retsamdaeh eht nommus ll’I“
na htiw deremmihs yeht dna
,secnocs gnimalf yb dessap
”.dekcuf ylhguoroht m’I“
.em ot siht did I .on ,lleW“
noitartsurf fo erutxim a htiw
”.yltnenimmi desaeler eb thgim uoy taht elbissop s’ti neht
”.desiarp eb sdoG“ .dehgis enialB