,tew a decalp eh dna ,did aI
.aruS htiw enod dah ehs woh egalliv eht dnuora pleh dluow ehs—
.nwo sih htiw elzzum reh delzzun dna
.mih rof denettalf sreh tub
.ton ro talf eb llits dluohs srae sih rehtehw ediced t’ndluoc eH .derutnev eh
.noitcerid aI-ton yreve ni gnikool tib tsal taht dias eH
”.yadot enola tfel eb ot stnaw ehs kniht I tuB“
egde eht revo gnireep
.teef sih ot tog dna ,deggurhs eH ”.hO“
”.kool a evah em tel
.tuh eht otni pu debmilc neht
senob eht yb ereh pu ssendam ot debmuccus uoy taht das si tI .llew ,hA
.ereh stnalp era ereht ,lleW“
.ruf reh tsniaga gnibbos mih leef dluoc ehs dna
yojne esaelP  .GNAF noos dna
tnew ti sa sessarg eht gnilppir
,mih rof yrros tlef aI
.senots eht dnuora selcric ni decar yeht os rethgit meht gnihsup
”.nruom lliw egalliv eht—
.trohs ylevitaler eb ot evorp did snossel ehT
.deneppah dah gnihton fi sa ,dednopser ummeH
.demraws dna tib yeht sa meht ta gnilialf
.rehtruf gnihton dias dna
”,gnihtoN“ .kcab derats ehS
,ummeH ot ,dekcinap
,ssarg eht ni rehtegot deniwtne yal yeht sa ruf rieht ni thgil fo snrettap etacirtni dehsalf
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,unutU yb
.emoh rof tuo gnittes erofeb
aI morf drawtuo dednapxe
.aI ot llef ksat eht
ecno ta noitisop ni sdrahs eht lla gnidloh yb
,reh ot desserP .evoba gnirewot
.revocer dluow ehs ylekilnu saw ti taht
.mih tuoba gnihton reh dlot srae sih taht ekil t’ndid ehs dna ,mih wonk t’ndid aI
deltsur ssarg ehT
,dedeen sa dia eht edivorp dluoc eH
esruoc fo ,nees eb t’ndluoc yehT
erus ekam ot dnA
htrae eht fo tuo tsurht
neht desilaer ehS .ummeH deirc
smaerts-yks eht desu aI
.niaga elbatrofmoc tlef sgniht dna
thgin ta nepo ti evael I semitemoS
top a riaper ot gniyrt ekil tsomla saw tI
,smaerts-yks eht dna werg yeht erehw
.stonk gniniamer eht ta gut ot deunitnoc aI
.nettogrof srats dna
,htrof dna kcab thgiew reh detfihs ehS .dennirg dna
retaw eht woleb decrof daeh sih
”.gniyalp tsuJ“ .deggurhs aI
.eno rehtona evah I ,taht yrrac uoY“
,ecalp siht ot yaw rieht edam dah yeht sa regnorts dna
”.eh t’ndid ,siht did eH“
kcab reh dessik eh tuB
,knabrevir eht fo yalc tew eht ni gnildees a dnuora gniggid ysub saw eh—
ummeH dna secips dna ssarg dna dniw eht fo llems eht
unutU yb ”ykS eht gnigduN“
,dnim t’ndid rehtom reh yletanutroF
.mrof s’nemaneK dnuora
noos ereh eb lliw nemaneK .aI ,yrrow t’noD“
,dessarrabme saw eh dias taht yaw taht ni devom srae sih dna ,delims ummeH
.gnitsiwt dna gnirednaem smaerts-yks fo sepor eht yb desiremsem
.erew yeht evissam ylurt woh ees dluoc ehs
,dluoc ehs esuaceb tsuj
,deb s’ummeH fo ssarg eht
.sknaht sih deddon ummeH elbaresim a dna
eno ni nemaneK ta dniw eht gnihsup
noisserpxe s’ummeH ta delggig dna
,deneppah dah revetahw riaper ot tpmetta na ni yltneuqerf yb eb dluow eh gniyas
,egalliv eht fo strikstuo eht no raf
,meht fo sderdnuH
,daeh sih tsniaga denettalf erew srae s’ummeH
,sselb ot sporc ,dnet ot sdnuow
,maerts-yks deit eht ta ereht saw eh ylneddus dna
”,oN“ ”.evael tsum uoY
.lla retfa ,sgniht gnitseretni fo dlot eH
.dleifa rehtruf degnar ummeH dna aI os
.niaga reh morf trapa eb reven d’eh erows eh
.esnes ekam ot nageb stonk eht erehw emac yad A
.stnalp yhtlaeh fo tserof elbatirev a saw tuh s’ummeH litnu gnol ton saw ti dna
psarg etiuq t’ndluoc aI
smaerts-yks eht pat ot woh
tnamada saw rehtom reh taht retfa dna
”,namahs eb dluow I“
.derrucco dah tahw rof meht ot dengissa saw emalb on dna
.dniheb tfel dah eh sksat eht pu tilps ot woh ssucsid ot tseb eb dluow ti dna ,denialpxe eh
.namahs eb ot erised on evah I
.mih htiw yrc neve t’ndluoc ehS
.dias aI ”,esoppus I“
,tuh s’ummeH fo elddim eht ni ,ereht doots ehS
.kaerb d’yeht taht hcum os smaerts-yks eht gnidneb saw ehs ekil tlef ti semitemos
,reh gnidnuorrus stonk eht ta dekculp aI
enots fo sregnif eguh eht ot
,ylfeirb desuap ohw
,reh dnuora dleihs eht ta derettab ehS .gnihton dnA
.smra reh dessorc ehS ”?uoy era ohW“
,sdrib fo lrihw dna
.meht dnuora soahc ni
.reh dael meht tel tub
,nettogrof yliratnemom srevir-yks
stnerruc s’revir ehT
sruoloc sti
draws eht pu tnew yeht dna
,tuh rieht ta reh dnuof ummeH
.elbissop sa llams sa eb ot gniyrt saw eh ekil dekool llits eh tub
,rehcaet tneitap a saw aruS
.revo now yllautneve saw
”.meht tae t’now sgniht rehto ro stibbar os dnA
.htaeneb dum eht otni
.sselrewop eb dluow renoititcarp delliksnu na dna
,lriws ot nageb sdniw eht dna
”,lliw ruoy ot meht gnidneb fo ecnatropmi eht uoy wohs ot deirt ev’I“ .deksa aI
,stop suoirav htiw deffuts t’nerew ti fi llams leef aI edam evah dluow tI
,meht dneb nac uoy fI“
yrc ot detrats ummeH
.egalliv eht ni relaeh eht ot edivorp dluoc eh taht sbreh fo egatrohs on saw ereht dna
,saw eh sa nworg neve dna
,retfaereht rehcaet reh eb ot saw aruS
,revarb eno edam rotaripsnoc-oc a gnivaH
,snosaes dewollof snosaeS
enod erew snossel s’aI litnu
.repsihw a ylerab saw ti dna ,deganam aI ”,oN“
,dnim nwo reh edisni dekcol llits flesreh dnuof ehs
.ecin dednuos taht thguoht aI
sbreh eht reh dewohs eH
,rehtom reh ot klat ot enog dah cennef dlo eht yltnerappA
,retaw pu gnihguoc
.ees dluoc ehs sa pu raf sa ot
smaerts-yks eht ot gnikaeps taht
,woleb dnuorg eht ot tuh eht morf reddal trohs eht nwod kcab debmilc ehS .did ehs oS
,secaf rieht revo derettacs erew sgnivrac dna shpylg ddo—
.gniht yvaeh a saw
.yalp ot owt uoy evael ll’I
.evoba thgin eht kcirp ot nageb srats eht sa
emit ot emit morf tub
,reh dnuora lla tneloder
,dah ehs noitcennoc ynit eht hguorht dluoc ehs lla denommus aI dna
,reh gninimaxe fo wohs a edam eH
,smaerts-yks eht htiw htworg rieht xaoc pleh ot elba saw aI
senots eht raen gnitcesretni lla ,ygrene htiw gniraor ,srevir
,retaL .emas eht tsuj
”,emas ehT“ ”?ehs si woH“
,nemaneK“ ”.yats tonnac uoY
.don elbitpecrepmi tsomla nA ”?nemaneK
.ssergorp saw ti tuB
mih dessik aI dna
cennef yob eht fo ecnaraeppa neddus eht tub ,srae reh dnuora shtaerw deruolocitlum
htaed ruoy ot tpael dna
,yvaeh dna kciht smaerts-yks eht
”.esaesid a saw erehT
llihpu depols yltneg draws eht taht dnoyeb tub—
,egalliv eht morf yawa draws eht gnola epolsnwod rehtruf rednaem ot
,ekirts ot swap reh delliw ehS
.smaerts-yks eht dewollof dna
.erom dna erom od ot reh gniksa
.pu evig ton did aI
.ti gnippord rebmemer neve t’ndid ehS
meht dnif I dna ,sbreh tuoba nrael I
,raeh etiuq t’ndluoc ehs cisum eht ot gnola demmuh ehs daeh reh nI
.emoh reh raen eb ot dediced ylraelc d’yeht
,cinap ot detrats eh litnu
.ezeerb eht ni gnivaw
.stnalp gniworg fo sneerg tnereffid eht lla htiw dellif
krow tluciffid erew hcihw fo lla ,eurt ylf ekam ot sraeps dna
,deddon aI .emit a ta eno
,tresed eht dehcaorppa dna sdnalssarg eht tfel ti sa revir eht dewollof yehT
,dednamed ehs ,spih no swaP
,ssarg llat eht ni peedeenk
”,thgirla eb ll’I“
!meht hguorht nar smaerts eht fo ynam oS .sregnif ekil
.senots eht fo eno tsniaga gninael
semit wef a siht detaeper ehS .niaga kcab neht
gnilevart elihw llew uoy evres lliw tub ,sey ,emit revo kael lliw tI
.gniddeb rieht hserfer ot ssarg tfos
.trofmocsid sih gniwohs morf srae sih pleh ton dluoc eh
.dias ehs ”,aI m’I“
,reh hsup dluow eH
.ti revoc ot esu dluoc eh taht edih fo palf eht detartsnomed ummeH ,ecnalg suoiruc s’aI ta
!os thguohT“ .dexaler ehs dna
.ereht saw yob eht tegrof tsomla dluoc ehs
,pleh sih dedeen ohw esoht lla troppus ot elbissopmi esiwrehto eb dluow tI
.thgilnus teg stnalp eht os yad eht gnirud nepo ti evael I“
,gniod saw eh tahw llet ton dluoc ehS
.neht ekops nemaneK ”.ecracs era smaerts eht erehw
reh dehctaw eh sa ecnelis sih dna
swodaem eht ni tuo saw ehS
srae sih ,tnemom a rof tnelis saw ummeH
?thgir ,snossel trohs ylno era yeht ,lleW“
,ylniatrecnu doots eh erehw ruf s’ummeH gnirrits dna
don yldneirf a ummeH evag cennef rehto ehT
neprahs ot sedalb retnuh
dniw fo nips eht hctaw dna meht egdun
.hcnurc a htiw kcor gnittih daeh sih
.tsol eb dluow eh dna
.meht dewollof dna revir eht yb dum tew eht ni stnirpwap sih dnuof ehs esuaceb syawla t’nsaw ti dnA .ti ta rednow ot detrats ehs netfo os ummeH otni depmub ehS
tsuj ot elbatrofmoc erom raf saw tI
,taeH ni deraeppa sah krow dehsilbup siH
.taht tuoba nrael ot tnaw t’ndid aI dna
.swap reh depsarg eH
.reh gnilcricne maerts-yks eht detsiwt yltfed eh dna
,srevir-yks eht fo tfew dna praw eht dna aI yb dexaoc
.mih gnicudortni ,dias aruS
.neht ,aI ta revo decnalg aruS ”.tnesba ro
,meht fo owt eht ot llaf dluow seitud s’aruS
niar ekam ot smaerts-yks eht gnisu fo dlot eH
.gninepo eht revo gnilgnad swaptoof reh
meht dellac dah aruS
,reh no seye esoht leef dluoc ehS
epolspu ffo tes ehS
,elcric a ni denrut ylwols dna
”.meht dnet I erehw tuh ym yb worg ot meht ekat dna
,syawla sa ,srae sih dna
?ereht kcirt elttil ruoy od ot elba neeb uoy evah gnol woh ,oS .aruS m’I
,mih etarbelec ot etir eht tA
,tuh ecin a saw tI
,smaerts-yks eht fo og tel ehs sa
”!sbreh erom dnif og s’teL“
,rae reh ta repsihw a
ummeH dettap eh
,meht fo dioved secalp ynam erew ereht—
.flaheb sih no flesreh yojne ot deirt dna
,sreh gnihcraes ecaf deirrow sih
,srehto eht tsgnoma kcab gnidnats
lla ti fo ssenneddus eht tub
,won renniht saw ummeH
.erom ecno ssarg eht otni ffo nar dna
,sniamer s’nemaneK ta yawa tae dluow ereht sdniw ehT
.scennef nezod a naht rellat
.dias rehtom reh
.tser eht nethgit dluow ti
.resolc devom ummeH sa
,won meht tsgnomA
.pu hctac ot nar ehS
,tnatsiser saw ehS
,ssargdeb emos no tis ot reddal eht pu reh depleh dna
dniw fo slrohw elttil gnitpmorp
,hguone saw ti meht neewteB
,dlo saw eH .deid aruS
htrae eht otni yvaeh taeb smurd eht elihw
elcricne yeht litnu meht ecrof
,ylgniwonk delims aharI
dloh dluoc yeht sa hcum sa detcelloc yeht dna—ynam erew ereht—
.deretsulf aI dah llits
,seilfrettub htiw detaroceD
ummeH rof taht did ehs tuB
.gnivom ton saw ydob reh taht gnisilaer erofeb
llew saw tuh ehT
srae egral reh dna hctiwt sreksihw reh edam tI .hcum oot delgnit sgnihT
sbreh dairym fo sllems eltbus dna prahs ,tnereffid ,ycips
.kcab deppets eh dna deppid srae siH
ummeH ta kcab decnalg ehS
decselaoc yltfiws yeht gnigdun reh ta dna
,noitcerid s’ummeH ta edistuo stop ytpme ynam eht fo eno ni
reh rehtob ton did gnidnats ehT .deilper aI
.revir eht fo knab eht ta dehcuorc
.desimorp sa ,yb emac nemaneK yad txen ehT
,reh tuoba meht evow dna
,pup a llits hguoht ,saw ehs naht reggib saw eH
,ummeH dna reh tsuj
stuh rehto tsgnoma dnuow htap reh sa
,won gniht tnereffid a saw reirrab reH
”?yrros m’I meht lleT“ .delims yob ehT
”.drah oot flesreh dehsup evah tsum ehS
.ummeH ,yrros m’I“
,seiradnuob esoht dehsup yeht
.tsrif eciov sih dnuof eh tub
.oot sgniht rehto tub
.thgin ta peels neve dluoc ummeH woh derednow ehs ynam os—
edis sih ta nwod tlenk ehS
,tnew ehs sa evoba smaerts-yks eht gnigdun
.ereht llits saw ehs ecnahcffo eht no
,ereht llits saw nemaneK tub
.esruoc fo ,deunitnoc aruS htiw snosseL
”?ereh senots eht hguorht gnivaew
,wen gnihtemos deganam ehs ylisae woh ta esirprus yppah sih sserpxe dluow eh nehw dna
,gnihtemos gniod saw eh leef mih ekam ot
,seye sih ni yruf saw erehT
.ummeH reh dah ehs
”?gniod uoy era tahw dnA“
,reh ta hsup dluow aruS ,snossel reh tA
,ssarg eht tsgnoma ereht yal yeht dna
,nwo sti fo lliw on dah ti fi sa deyebo ydob reH
tib yb tib derettacs tser eht
,eciov sih tniap yrrow dna kcohs fo ruovalf a tel eH
”,nwod yaw gnol a s’tahT“
”?tsal yeht od gnol woH“
”.srats eht ees nac I os
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”!ummeH tsuJ ,seilfrettub ym debrutsid uoy ,lleW“ .dias eh
,ssentiw ot ummeH ylno htiw
ysion saw ti rof
delrihw ebirt eht dna straeh rieht otni dna
.sedis reh ta ylpmil yal yeht tub
,emoh dellac rehtom reh dna ehs tuh eht raen
gnihcaet saw aruS tahw no desucof ehs fi taht dnuof noos aI
,ti ni delever ehs dna ruf reh ni derettulf tI
,stnecs fo ylponap tnatsnoc a saw tI
,emit s’ummeH dna s’aI saw ti won ,won roF
,dleiy ton dluow dna yreppils erew stsiwt dna stonk ehT
ecnarticlacer ot noitisopsiderp s’aI neve dna
”.niaga pleh dna yrt dna
,sretnuh rehto eht htiw tuo saw rehtom reh ecniS
,nemaneK ni noitcaer elttil saw erehT
trats ylurt ton did yad hcae dna
.ecnartne s’tuh eht ta
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
reffus ot emos wolla ot decrof eb dluow eh ,ti tuohtiw rof
,gnol eht fo seldnub gnitcelloc ysub
,snoitome sih fo ekops srae sih yaw eht dekil ehS
.tsefinam yresim sih
,dekcilf seye reH
.dnatsrednu t’ndluoc ehs syaw ni dettonk dna depraw smaerts eht
.ti nihtiw neerg fo tuorps tseinit eht
.senots eht edistuo secap lareves ,kcab srae
,kcab klaw eht no htap nwo sih edam dah nemaneK
.detats aI ”,smaerts-ykS“
,oot ,ereht saw nemaneK
suoiruc dna deticxe leef reh edam yeht tuB .tsael ta
.gnitcartsid ylemertxe dna
,mih ot reh deldarc eh thgin tA
.edivorp dluoc smaerts-yks eht tahw fo seiradnuob eht hcterts ot ,erom dna erom
,ni ssargdeb erom gnirb mih pleh ot
.depmuj aI dna ,dehgual aruS
!seilfrettuB fo retsaM ,aI“
,lla ta wonk ton did ummeH ynaM
.gnorw ylbirret enog s’gnihtemoS
.mih ruonoh ot seilfrettub dna sdrib eht dellac aI
.mraw lla leef dluow aI
noisufnoc ni gninettalf dna gnikrep dna gnileviws
,mih fo saw ehs sa reh yb desirprus sa tsuj demees eH
.dedeen ehs lla saw ummeH .delriws dna
.deciton nemaneK dna
senots gnidnats eht morf yawa reh del nemaneK dna
.denruter yeht nehw etal saw tI
,ekat dluow ti sa gnol sa
,denettalf srae htiw erugif ylenol a ,ummeH gnivael
sllems eht lla ta delknirw elzzum reH
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.reirrab reh nihtiw doots dna ,ffo ti gniyt
.denetsil evah dluohs uoY“ .won resolc
,stfut yrros owt ro eno ot dehsinimid dah dekculp d’ehs ssarg fo dnuom egral eht
,etavirp ni ecitcarp dluow ehs oS
thgil s’erifnob eht htiw gnirettilg seye sih
.noitcerid rehto eht deirt yeht yad eno ,oS
.egdel eht morf sedirts wef a tub saw ehs nehw tuo dellac eciov s’ummeH
.nemaneK naht regnorts saw ehs ,lla retfA .dias aI
.saw ti tahw rof ti llet dluoc aI tub
smaerts-yks eht ta degdun ehS
.woleb raf dehsarc sevaw erehw ot
.sgnisselb reh htiw tuo rethguad reh deoohs dna
!meht rof drow taerg a s’tahT“
esraps era smaerts-yks eht nehw neve
.mih no dnal d’yeht taht os
.dnuora era uoy fi ,taht sa ti ees ton lliw elpoeP“
gnirob saw taht—egalliv eht saw maertspU
,reh ekat swaptoof reh tel ehS .gnirolpxe og ot
.sgniod egalliv dna
,tnatsni na ni ereht saw ummeH
,shtilagem eht sdrawot
tuo erew srats eht nehw
”!ummeH ,tuh ruoy ekil I“
,ddo leef reh edam tahT
.ereht reh peek ot tneiciffusni saw weiv naeco eht fo llup eht dna ,aI deirrow tI
,enola tfel neve tuB
”.uoy ees ot teg I ,dnA
,taht ta deifillom saw aI
,syawla sa llits srae sih
.tuo meht tpek reirrab eht tub
esolc mih dleh aI
.aI ot noitnetta sih denrut dna
niaga mlac saw ecaf sih ylneddus dna
.gnihton gnitacidni
.enod dah eh tahw revocsid ot gniyrt
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.pleh ot smaerts-yks eht htiw neve
dexelf smaerts-yks ehT .mih no desucof
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.reh dnuora tibro na pu koot seilfnogard eht dna—
.reh ot gnidaelp dna reh ot gniklat
.tuoba derehtag tsuj
.no neht morf tuh s’ummeH ni devil aI
.edistuo smaerts-yks eht hsurb dluoc aI tub ,dleh llits stonk ehT .ereht mih dleh rewop s’nemaneK sa yletarepsed dekcik eH
,elbarapesni erew yehT .erom dna erom
,htolcniol dna ruf reh fo noitanibmoc a no ffo yalc eht depiw
,ecruos a hcus htiw tresed eht ssorca uoy wollof dluow seilfrettub ruoY“
”?uoy t’nera ,lrig s’aharI er’uoY
.meht evoba tuo daerps yks eht fo esnapxe esnemmi eht ni tub
.erom ecno denrut dna denrut noom ehT
.ynomerec ega fo gnimoc rieht dah ummeH dna ehs
.ylsuovren ,dias ehs
.oot deppots ssarg fo naeco eht gnilppir sezeerb gnilriws eht dna
,sezis tnereffid ,sruoloc tnereffid
”.sbreh tcelloc nac ew dna uoy dnuora eb ot tnaw tsuj I
”.tuh ym uoy wohs ll’I dna kcab meht ekat ll’eW
,taht ta tnemeticxe ni llat doots srae siH
,devirra ehs nehw ereht saw nemaneK
.revir ybraen eht fo nobbir thgirb
,dedne dleif eht erehw ssarg eht ni hcamots sih no gniyl saw eh ;tey ton
,od cennef gnuoy a seod esle tahW
.gnihsiruolf erew sbreh s’ummeH .eb
.tuh eht ot kcab reh dael ot detrats yltneg eh sa
.knabrevir eht gnihcaorppa nemaneK deciton eh sa
,ti fo tsdim eht ni dnA
.rof gnikool m’I tahw s’tahT .sbreH
,stop eht ni htrae eht saw ereht—
;yad txen eht kcab eb dluow eH
.enod dah eh tahw dna nees dah eh tahw fo ekops eh
,doirep dednetxe na rof tceffe na rewop ot uoy selbane osla tI
.elggig ot ton deirt ehS .tnemhsaba dna
”,won snosaes wef a rof em htiw gniyduts neeb sah nemaneK“ .oot smaerts-yks reh desu eh taht
saelp dna sdrow fo maerts a—
dniw fo noisolpxe desirprus A .eciov eht emac
depoows seilferif reh sa
”?lla meht htiw od uoy od tahW“
,rewsna t’ndluoc ehS
”.tnaw uoy fi revo keep tsuj nac uoY !yrrow t’noD“
laiceps yrev s’tI
ezag suoredrum s’nemaneK sa
,nageb seitivitsef eht nehw suovren erew htob dna
.tisiv txen s’nemaneK htiw naelc depiw saw edam dah ehs yawdaeh ynA .xelpmoc os saw ti tub ,tib yb tib meht krow dluoc ehs dna
.kaeps ot htuom reh denepo ehS
.dessap syad eht dnA
.od I tahw s’tahT“ ”?yhW“
,resolc tog nemaneK
.yppah aI edam hcihw
”ykS eht gnigduN“ saw sihT
,mih ot stnialpmoc reh gnitaeper dehsinif ehs emit driht eht yB
.epacse ton dluow ehs
.nemaneK saw eman siH
reh ta kool dluow eh—
.aruS gnipleh morf thgis yb wenk ylno aI scennef ynam erew ereht dna suoretsiob dna
”!em ot kaepS ?aI“
ertnec egalliv eht ni ecalp koot tI
yadot tub ,ecalp emas eht ni syawla t’nerew yehT
,niaga detcartsid
.ti dewollof ehs sselnu
.ti tuoba gnihton od dluoc ehs tub
”.sruoy eb nac tahT
nrut srats eht hctaw dna
,tresed eht ot nekat eb ot saw ydob s’nemaneK taht saw sredle eht fo noisiced ehT
wap reh dettap eH
,llef eH .tsrub prahs
.thguoht ni peed saw eh nehw did yeht sa gnivom
,htob meht rof moor saw ereht os ti fo ytnelp
htrae eht fo senob eht
nrut sih emac ti nehw dna
.dias eh tahw ot esnes saw ereht tub
,sdon fo tsellams eht deganam ehS
,stcesni gniylf dairym ot emoh erew revir eht fo sknab ehT .hguone saw tI
.esir nus eht hctaw ot revir eht ot klaw reh depleh ummeH sa neve
.tuh ym ni flesym yb m’I“
.eno teiuq a er’uoy ,lleW“
.ummeH teem ot yaw eht no dnif dluoc ehs gnihtyreve ot hcus sa denoitnem dna ,rehcaet a tnaw t’ndid aI
,edis sih yb ereht eil d’ehs dna
.dehsup ehs drah woh rettam on
mih dnuora snrettap lriws ot erifnob eht morf skraps thguorb ehS
.ton dluoc ehs tub
.denialpxe eh ,egalliv eht fo erac ekat ot mih delbane ylurt tahw saw tI .delims eh
.edistuo stnalp eht fo emos gnivom pu dedne yeht taht gnitcartsid os semitemos saw ti dna
.reh no kcehc emoc ot emit eht gnikam syawla
,senots esnemmi eht sdrawot dedaeh ehs daetsnI
.evaew a ni sdaerht ekil
,tfel dna denrut aruS ,taht htiW
.revir eht sdrawot nar yllufeelg ehs sa wollof ot meht denokceb ehs
,raeh etiuq t’ndluoc ehs cisum saw tI .ylmodnar leviws
.ruf reh nopu tila yeht sa sehcuot thgil-rehtaef
,neht ,enod eb ot hcum t’nsaw erehT
.gnihton reh llet dluow srae sih sa neve ,seye rettib htiw
.stonk gniniamer eht ta gnillup yllacitnarf
.taht ni enola eb ot derreferp evah dluow ehs dediced ehS
,knar sih evah nemaneK teL
ekil t’ndid ehs dna
meht dnuora kciht smaerts eht no desucof ehS
.stnuh eht morf kcab doof thguorb syawla rehtom s’aI .esnes edam tahT
did syawla eh sa ,reh ot ekops eH
ereht saw nemaneK nehw tpecxE
.wap sih koot ehs os
”!llew sa meht ees nac uoy taht
wap sih no deggut ehs
smaerts-yks eht dna
,won ummeH dna flesreh tsuj saw tI
,secnalg suoiruc owt ro eno dna
,denetsil sredle eht sa edis reh yb doots ummeH   .der htiw degnit
”,sbreh emos dnuof I“
”,ummeH tsuJ“ ”?uoy era ohW
htrae eht tem yeht erehw morf
,meht ta dettaws eH
,smets gnirevaw no gnithgila dna srewolfdliw eht tsgnoma gnittilf ,ereht esuaceB
.dessap dah emit retfa ti hsinelper dna ,ffo ti eit
,detaralihxe dna gnitnap
,ffo meht eit dna
,yadot gnorts saw gnilgnit eht tuB
.snoitcerid lla ni derettacs seilfrettub eht dna reh deltrats
.llirht eht htiw gnitarbiv srae egral reh
.ereht devil dah ohw wonk t’ndid tub
yrt ot eunitnoc dluow eh dias dna
.dnas erom dna dnas tsuj
.teef reh ot reh dellup dna
,htrae eht fo senob eht—
;aI ot thgir leef t’ndid ti tuB
,eciov sih draeh tsuj ehS
.lliw reh ot dneb ot gnilliw naht erom demees
.sucof t’ndluoc aI
nemaneK dna aI dna
,teef sih ot delggurts ummeH
.gnihton od dluoc ehs tuB
,sessarg gniltsur fo
.mih dnif ot ffo hsur dluoc ehs dna
.yawa reh dekcol taht maerts deit eht gnicrofnier ylluferac elihw eht lla ,sesion ’tut-tut‘
,egalliv eht tsap deklaw yeht rehtegot dna ,wap reh koot eH
.eson sih no dednal ylfrettub eht nehw
neewteb noitalerroc a saw ereht denimreted oga gnol dah yehT
.ylthgils wap sih dezeeuqs ehs taht hguone tsuj—
,ti dias eh nehw nettalf t’ndid srae sih woh
denialpxe eh ,erehwyreve ton erew smaerts-yks ehT
,senob sih revoc dnas eht tel ot
.sbreh fo stop dairym dna
”,ton ro smaerts-yks
.deklaw d’ehs htap eht gnola
,don yrotcnufrep a reh evag eH
.hcum os truh ti dna
.oot sesiarp sti gnis dluoc yeht os
stonk eht fo emos delgnatnu ehS
”!mih wohs ot tiaw tonnac I
”?gniod uoy era tahW“
dedracsid shtolcniol
tuh eht derahs ummeH dna aI oS
esiwrehto rednow dluow eH
,hguoht ,tnetsisni saw eH
.reh denethgirf ti dna
,sezeerb dna sgub dna sdrib dna seilfrettub tsuj ton saw tI
.gnorts er’uoy fi ,erom ebyaM ?spahrep ,yad A
,resolc emac eh sa
.pat ot uoy rof ereht eb lliw rewop rieht neht ,daerht desolc a
,nemaneK ta kool ot daeh reh nrut ot deirt ehs
”!ffilc eht dnuora luferac eB
”!swap ruoy tuo dloH“
”?emos yrrac em pleh ot tnaW“
saw tI .hguone gniticxe kool t’ndid osla tI
,gut dna eno pirg ot erew ehs fi neve dna
.daerd dna tnemeticxe fo erutxim a htiw gnilggirw
,deifirroH .ni reh dnA
,sih fo seye esoht htiw reh ta kool dluow nemaneK neht dna
wap reh depsarg eH
,deilper eh ”,neht ,yrros ma I“
”?tahW“ .gnola meht thguorb eno
.daeh sih tsniaga talf srae sih
dleif neerg ,taerg a ni
,did ehs sgniht rehto eht tuB
.reh detatirri eh—
?tahw ot oN ?oN“
rekciht nettog dah smaerts-yks eht
gninepo eht fo egde eht no dnal ot revo sdrib emos degdun dna ,deralced ehs
,aI oT .tnereffid
,gnidnats neeb tsuj dah ehs
,emac emit eht nehW
rehtie ,enots knalb tsuj ton erew yehT
.ekaw reh ni wollof ot
,srats eht derahs dna
”.yalp emoc llits nac uoY
,hguone tnasaelp saw eciov siH
”!aes eht llems nac I !no emoc ,aI“
,llat doots senots eguh
ssargdeb eht derahs dna
uoy erA ?aI“ .dekrep srae sih dna dnuora deppihw daeh siH
,won ereh m’I ,lleW“
.ereh er’uoy dalg m’I !ummeH ,hA“
”?ereht
,snossel rieht gnirud erom rof ksa dna
.sdnas eht otni raf sretnuh eht deinapmocca dna
,tuh s’ummeH fo gninepo eht hguorht ton
.dneb nac uoy maerts a kciht woh sdnepeD“
.ereh pu spup ees netfo t’nod I“
.derevocsid aI
,saw ummeH erehw saw emoH
.oga snosaes ynam stirips eht denioj stnerap yM
”?edisni stnalp ruoy lla era yhW“ .nrut ylwols
.yaw hcihw yreve gniog srae sih
.lliw nwo reh fo evom ro kaeps tonnac ehs—
.sseldne tsomla tlef taht sthgin ni
,rehto eht ot wap eno morf thgiew reh detfihs ehS
,esruoc fo ,sselnU
erolpxe ot sdnalssarg fo esnapxe na htiw aI tfel taht dnA
deraems dna yssem htolcniol dna swap sih
.tnemssarrabme ni dehsulf srae sih sa gnihgual
,yllufniap sreh dehcnelc wap s’nemaneK .tpael traeh s’aI !ummeH
”.oot uoy seirrow eh wonk I dna ,em seirrow eH“
,meht gnoma flesreh dnuof aI ,gnihguaL
yks thgin eht ees ot teg netfo t’ndid ehs os
.seilfrettub erew
.esruoc fo ,ti fo ummeH dlot ehS
”?od stnerap ruoy tahw taht sI“
,yks eht rof dehcterts taht senots eht ot epols eltneg eht pu
.emit ot emit morf tuh s’ummeH ni revo yats reh tel neve dna
.ecrof lluf ni eciov rehcaet sih ,dednopser aruS
.eryp a evresed ton did eh rof
,niht eht sdrawot
.daeh sih tsniaga rettalf neve tog wohemos srae s’ummeH dna
ereht doots tsuj cennef wen eht ecnis
sdaerht eht ees nac uoY“ ”.elihw A“
nrael dluohs ehs taht
,reh dleh taht maerts eht ta dekop ehS
trapa reve yldrah erew yehT
aruS ot dneterp dluow ehs os dna
,ereht egalliv eht morf yob a saw erehT .deppots dnA
,seitud ecitnerppa no ekat ot denrael
,dna aes eht fo tlas eht etsat dluoc ehS
cennef gnuoy yna rof nosaer hguone saw taht dna ,dne no dnats ruf reh dna
.taht tuoba dab tlef aI dna
”.stnuh eht morf doof em sevig eh nruter nI .relaeh eht ,ikinA ot meht evig I“
.og mih dehctaw aI dna
.seitiliba reh fo erom wohs dluoc ehs tlef ehs
ssarg eht tsgnoma edistuo gnittis
”.gnihton ekil kool t’ndiD“ .aI dias
.namahs eno ylno eb dluohs erehT“ .deunitnoc neht
tlef taht ria eht ni srevir elttil ekil erew yeht—
ereh gnorts erew yeht—
”?dnuora syawla uoy era yhW“
,drow sih ot eurt saw nemaneK
.htrae eht fo senob eht ta pu gninrom txen eht mih teem ot reh deksa eh ,sdrawretfA
.hguoht ,hcum oot toN
tuh eht ot reh del ummeH
,meht neewteb ni ssem yalc
.egalliv eht dnuora sksat sih ni aruS gnipleh
,nwod deid dah snoitarbelec eht dna
ffo delevel yllanif ti litnu
.erom ecno ffo reh esolc ot gninnigeb ,ti gnikniker
smaerts-yks eht degdun ehS
gnikam dna daeh sih gnikahs
enohs tesnus fo knip dna dlog ehT
,ummeH ta revo decnalg tluda ehT
ummeH gniriapsed a denraw tub
maerts-yks ybraen eht htiw seilfnogard emos degdun ehs dna ,ddo fo epyt doog a saw ti tub
mih dedworc erom dna erom tub
!noos ereh eb lliw nemaneK“
mrof ot seilfrettub gniniamer eht dedausrep dah ehS
,seimene yawa hsup dna
detneler eh litnu
reh etartsurf dluow ti wenk ehs dna ,ecalp etiuq t’ndluoc ehs stnecs
reddal eht edisa gnidnats
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.yllacitehtapmys elzzum suoires sih don dluow eh dna ,elggurts a saw
reh nekorb evah smaerts-yks eht fi sa si tI
.yad emas eht no meht evah ot etairporppa demees ti os
,esruoc fo ,efas t’nsaw ti taht raf os toN
.deggurhs ehS ”?dniw eht htiW
,eraperp ot senicidem erew erehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.htaeneb sessarg gnol eht evoba desiar ti peek ot stlits trohs sti htiw
,nwo s’aI ekil hcum dna
.enola ton er’uoy os ,oot meht ees I
.ti tneverp dluoc taht gnihtemos ton erew smaerts-yks eht dna
,skaerts-raet htiw denekrad ecaf sih
.naeco eht revo tuo gnikool ni ummeH denioj
,hguoht ,did ummeH .og ton did aI
?maor ot modeerf htiw
eht lla dna ,flesmih ummeH
.raf oot tlef taht tub
;llaw edis depols eht ni gninepo egral a yb til-
snoissucsid tnatropmi dna sgnirehtag labirt dna
,reh ot meht dexaoc ehs—
,edistuo peels ot efas t’nsaw ti dias rehtom reH
.retaw fo lluf saw ti elihw—
dluohs yeht sa erew sgniht taht wenk aI dna
swolb tcelfed dna smrots dna
.deid dna derettups slrohw ehT
.era uoy yhw wonk I kniht I ,llew ,dnA
.wollof ot smaerts-yks dna
,aruS htiw enola saw ehs nehW
.ssarg eht ni snrettap gnicart
,smaerts-yks rof dehcaer ehS
.emoh erew ehs dehsiw aI taht os
”,hsiw uoy fI“ .ylpmis ,dias eh
,yllaniF .dlo dekool eH
,deppots ehs ,won revir eht raeN
.smaerts-yks reh erew yehT
,ygrene suovren fo lluf ,dias eh ”,ti ekil t’nod I“
erew yeht fi sa won saw ti dna
,tuh eht ta kcab flesreh dnuof ehs emit eht yB
hguoht ,ereht cennef rehto ehT
.deppid elzzum reH
,noisserpxe sih ni erofeb nees t’ndah aI gnihtemos fo hsalf a saw erehT .detats aI
,eerf elggiw ot detrats yehT
;lla t’nsaw taht tuB
.meht hctaw nac I os ,hO“
.ummeH kcurtsewa na rof retal meht ecudorper yllufeelg dluow ehs dna
.elzzum eht fo edis eht ni mih kcurts kcor ehT
.gninepo eht hguorht reh decaf nus eht nehw gnitniuqs
,eciwt ro ecno ,erofeb ti nees dah ehS
,)unutUgoDdliW@( unutU yb ”ykS eht gnigduN“
gnithgif ekil dednuos taht fo emos tub
tnalp reh deppolp ehS
retniw tahT   .enola ummeH dna
.dellac ehs nehw reh ot denetsil lla—rehtaew eht ,stnalp ,slaminA
,rehtona pu gnikcip ,dehcuorc ummeH
.suoregnad eb dluoc yeht rof ,ylreporp
,yob elbisnes a demees eH
.ffilc eht sdrawot
.krad saw tnecs siH .llits srae
,noisiv fo dleif reh fo tuo dna ni yltnatsnoc saw eH
,reh ta dennirg eH
.rettam ton did ti ,yletaidemmi tsomla tub
,swollahs eht otni gnulf saw ummeH dna
.nirg a htiw dias eh
,senots eht sdrawot dedaeh t’ndah ummeH
ruftsehc s’ummeH fo maerc eht no
desserdda eh elihw
.meht decrofnier eh sa stonk eht eitnu ot stpmetta kaew reh ffo dednef dna ,delwocs eH
,reh htiw decnad dna
.emit eraps sih ni gnitirw dna gnidliubdlrow syojne tub gnivil a rof semag setaerc ohw flow detniap a
;pu-nworg a saw senots eht fo eno tsniaga gninaeL
smaerts-yks eht gnigdun dna
,ega emas eht tuoba erew dna
,seilferif noos dnA
stnuh fo dlrow tluda ,egnarts taht ni sgniht gniod tuo yltneuqerf saw rehtom reH
srats eht dehctaw dna—