nihc ym htaeneb elzzum sih dekorts eH
raelcnu sa dezicitirc neeb yltneuqerf sah ecafretni resu dnasuohT ruoF kraM niarborciM ehT  .yrros ma I“
!semitemos ma I krej a tahW
.noitom drawrof otni ylhtooms gnizoo rac eht gnileef
.rac a tsuj toN .rac a
!siht ekil reven saw ti detam ew nehw
retspmud a ta mia koot I dna deilpmoc sivlE
—dna raeppasid su ekam ot desimorp dah I
.lortnoc ni ydaerla msagro eninac gniogno sih
”!timil emit a dah I em dlot reven uoY“
.yawa ti desae neht
deffuw eh yltfoS
.llits ti dloh ot stroffe ym etipsed flesti gniggaw-flah tpek liat derruf-emulp ym
.deneppah gnihtoN
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”?elbatpecca taht sI
”!niaga namuh em ekam ot dedeen uoy ecnadiug eht dah uoy dias uoY  ?raelc ton ti sI“
…ym ta gnikcil yllacitnarf
.denioj erew ew dna
?yvaeh eb yeht dluoW
!sehtolc gniraew saw I
.rennam evitcaorp a ni won thgir uoy ot esu fo eb yam I
epaga swaj nwod derats I
.nottub eht desserp eh dna ”!woN“
.tsul dna evol dna tliug fo elgnat gnilriws a sgnileef sih
.dne liat ym drawot ylyls elzzum sih ffins ot nageb dna sthguoht ym thguac sivlE
.rac a uoy ekam ot esoporp I“
,sserac sih tsniaga kcab delzzun I dna
,detarapes ew emit eht yb enog gnol saw rekoms ehT
.rehtegotla seippup evif reviled dluohs uoy snoitacilpmoc gnirraB
”?ti nepo uoy tseggus I yaM
.timmaD“ thguoht I
…seye ym desolc dna
.enog er’yeht lit‘ won teiuq tis ot evah ll’eW
.raelcnu saw ti fi yrros ma I  .tnemetats ym fo tnetni eht saw tahT“
,I saw os dna yrd erew sehtolc ehT
rae ym ssik-elzzun ot nug yar eht denodnaba eH
…fi regnad elttil a s’tahW
.rac a eb ot tnaw t’nod I  !oN“
,mih dnuora thgit dehctiwt-hcnelc I dna su demlehwrevo sgnileef eht litnu
.yzarc em gnikam …speek
”!reifirgomsnarT  .etunim a tiaw—
”!oga ruoh na flah em mrofsnart ot ydaer erew uoY
”?niaga namuh flesruoy ekam ot tnaw uoy erus yllaer uoy erA  !oot ti tlef uoY
.kcab dnah sih dehctans eh os ,gninraw ni delworg sivlE dna ruf ym hcuot ot fi sa
;em htiw ti tlef sivlE dna
.eerht taht ekam …tiaw ,on
.hcus emos ro ,wohs eigguZ dna greZ eht—mih no tuo dekalf sah puorg rehto emoS
.tnangerp ton erew uoy oga ruoh na flaH“
”.em no ema…hs ,hO“ ,derettum eH
.taht rewsna t’noD
?reifilpma eht saw erehW
”.ydaerla retteb gnileef si hctib eilloc pu dekconk ypmurg sihT
,drawpu elzzum ym tcerid esaelP
.yaw-yella nepo eht ni dnats ot
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
,neerg niatnuoM yekomS eessenneT yad-tneserp no srettel kcalb ni demialcorp ti ”VULYPPUP“
derettum yoreL dna ,ecno ta htob
…tub sdraug raluger tsuj er’ew dias I ekiL
!ssoB“ —dna ,desuap dna
.sthgil ytiruces yb til-llew ydaerla saw aera ehT
”?elamef llits yhw dnA“ ,depley I
”.devlovni era senomroh uoy llet nac I tub
”!ssoB ,nac ew eruS“
elzzum sih deffins sivlE dna pu deppilf liat yM
.noitseuq taht rewsna ot elbanu ma I tub ,yrros ma I“ ”?ti od uoy naC
,llew ees ot delzzad oot llits erew seye yM
.stnemetats hcus morf tnemecrofnier evitisop gnorts sevired gnimmargorp eroc yM
;hsur latnem fo tros tsegnarts eht neeb dah rehtegot sciryl esoht pu gnikaM  !gnos ylliS
”?ton yhW“ dekrab sivlE
.trihs ym htaeneb selppin fo swor eht morf erusaelp gnilgnit fo sevaw gnireggirt
.em ta dam eb t’nod esaelp …sivlE“
,oot daeh ym dekcoc I  ”?fraW“
”.krow taht ekam nac eW  .kO“ ”.ssoB ,seY“
”?aera gnikrap reporp eht ot em tcerid uoy naC  .hguoht ,yaw ym tsol evah ot mees I
tekcop peed sti ni
.yrd dna naelc saw em htaeneb etercnoc eht nevE
’.tnangerp emoceb ot ydaer dna elba‘
,pu ti koot dna ylregnig nwod dehcaer I—
kcab dedlof saw pot ehT
?ssoB“ em deksa dna edis eno ot daeh sih dekcoc eH
,elzzum ym demraw yliree dna
”!sruoH-retfA-dnalecarG ot emocleW  .uoy knahT  .thgir …rrE“
”—tub derb neeb d’uoY
,em revo gnidnats sivlE htiw niaga ekawa emac I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
!taeh ni llits er’uoy dnA
.notsnhoJ yoreL rentrap ym si enohp llec sih htiw gnissem yug taht dna nosugreF moT m’I“
”!meht fo erac ekat ll’I“
.eson ym hcuot ot pu ti delruc dna
niap gnihcterts fo bats a—
,em fo pot no pu flesmih werht sivlE dna
”…seulb pilf liat eht …on
,gnirewoprevo-raen saw rotarelecca eht no nwod wap ym pmots ot egru ehT ”!ereht ti dloH“
.dnah ym dnuora nwod dedacsac dna
.syug esoht tuoba togroF  .parC
ti …tnecs-taeh eht s’tI  .ssoB ,yrroS“
.depmurg I ”,hcum oot raf siht gnikil er’uoY“
,yhw mohtaf t’nac llits I
”.og ot yaw hcihw em wohs uoy fi won gnola evom ll’I dna tsol tog I yrros m’I  ?tey enod ew erA“
”goD ’nuoH a tub ’nihtuN“     yojne esaelP
.snug deirrac sdraug htob ylekil etiuq dna
.rehtegot thguoht ew ”?od siht lliW“
:ereh esahcrup moc.nozamA rof elbaliava si
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
ZZAK ”—tahw tuo dnif ot evah eW  !tiaW“
stseggus noitalume sihT
noitcepsni rof esolc eno dleh I
”!tnangerp eb t’nac I
pu degrus taht
em morf tuo dellup dna tfos knarhs tsal ta sivlE nehW
…tub stlem niarb ym lit‘ uoy wercs ot tnaw I siht ekil esolc uoy gnillemS  !oot yzarc m’I
.ereht uoy detartsac yeht …dnA
ecalp gnidih ruo morf tuo dezeeuqs dna dnah-wap eno ni nug-reifirgomsnart eht koot I  ”.seY“
.lla ta yaw siht tuo no gniog eb ot desoppus s’gnihton dna ,ytrap eht htiw ton ,sdraug ytiruces raluger tsuj er’eW
”?xes tub gnihtyna fo kniht uoy t’naC  !sivlE“
”…efas s’ti dna ,enola er’ew nehW
.sdraug eht ot yltcerid gnikaeps ,deppiy sivlE  ”!ereht eb ll’eW“
eltbus emos ni desuma demees enot s’enihcam eht dnim ym oT
”.wolg neila neerg avulleh a tuo stup ti dnA
.shgiht yrruf ym otni yletarepsed gniggid swalc tnulb delruc sih
”!sdrow ym tsiwt uoy fi uoy pots ot hguone trams ton m’I wonk uoY
,seippup eht tuoba dam er’uoy yrros m’I
.knalf yarg devruc emosdnah sih fo espmilg gnoledis a gnilaets ,ylitliug eson ym dekcil I dna
.yrrufoS dna ytiniffaruF no elbaliava era ”xoF s’pihS“ cimocbew dna seirots s’rednebraE  .yegreB leahciM flesmih sllac osla ohw ,rednebraE yb
!ksa ot thguoht neve reven I
”—tub derb neeb d’uoy ,nialpxe ot gnitpmetta saw I sA  .dnik tahT  .seY“
.sllib rallod derdnuh htiw dellif saw esactius ehT
noitom otni dellor ew sA
,rednebraE yb ”goD ’nuoH a tub
”.seulb pilf-liat toh-taeh eht tog eW“ ”!tops siht ot detoor em tog uoY“ !tonk eht eit s'teL !toh er'uoy ,serac ohW“ ”?desu gnieb I mA
,yawa denrut dna dehgis sivlE
”.derrucco sah noitazilitref lautca litnu tceffe ekat ton od sefas-liaf yM
”?eisoR tuoba wonk uoy oD
.em gnidnilb ,ecaf ym ta thgiarts thgilhsalf a detcerid eno dna
.emas eht od ot rentrap sih rof ylitsah denoitom dna ffo thgilhsalf sih denrut eH
terces a si ssecorp ehT“
,neht reifirgomsnart eht no noitnetta ruo dexif eW ”.ko…“ delffuw I
,flesti nug eht otni dekaos tub
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.tuo liat ym tel ot kcab eht ni tils a htiw triks dna trihs naiiawaH neerg-aes dna laroC
”.ti tuoba gnihton wonk I raews I deworrob uoy rac PIV a si siht fI
?em yortsed ot gniyrt uoy erA
”!erom rof lwoh tsuj…“ ”…on uoy lworg t'naC“
”.dnammoc ruoy tnemelpmi ot elbanu ma I tub yrros ma I“
!kcalc dna ti deppord I yawa thgiR
…dna won em htiw saw sivlE
.hguone kciuq ereht teg nac ehs fi dna
.tnereffid erew srebmun ehT
,si taht ,devom sterf ehT !devom yeht …dna
”.dnatsrednu I ,ssoB ,seY  .ot evah eW“ ”…ew …I“
.detseggus I ”,evael ot tes gnitteg er’eW“
!em ot kcab emoc dah eciov yM
,ti denrut I dna noitingi eht ni saw yek A
”—etiuq t’nac I  ?ma’aM uoy gnillac eb I dluohs …rO
neht yb su ediseb erew sdraug ehT
ll’I dna ,god ,egats no taht ekil klaT“ mih dlot I
.enihcam emit a ni ereht emoc dah ti ekil
kcab ym gnola niks ehT
”.god ’nuoh YM er’uoy
,eugnot eninac talf gnol a tuo kcuts I ?laer
”?taht raeh uoy diD
.noitcefrep tnagele ot deffulf dna debmoc ruf hcir ym
,pot dna yretslohpu edeus eulb htiw
.mih htiw tsul ni yldam llits ,revol denrut tep emosdnah ym no deips I eye eno fo renroc eht hguorhT
.hguoht ,ssenkrad lluf fo tfig eht detnarg ton erew eW
”?rac a ni gniod yeht kcuf eht tahW
etihw-lraep a demaelg
,dessarrabme gnikool dna gnitegdif saw nosugreF moT em ediseB
ecnaidar neerg fo niatnuof dna ssih tfos a tsuj
.taht retfa retlehs lamina eht ta uoy depmud yeht dna
,emit siht esion yna yldrah saw erehT
?deksa eh dah yhw ,yaw taht tlef eh fI
”—eht tahW“ deppiy I
.seY“ derepsihw sivlE
.detnelat erom dna ,gnikool retteb hcum eb ot pu em edaM
,ecno ta htob spirg ruo desaeler ew litnu—
.yawa evom ot deliaf maeb thgilhsalf ehT
”?gnikrow s’ti nehw esion ekam gniht reifirgomsnart siht seod
,dessih I ”!rac eht ni teG“
.kcehc ni ti dleh I tub
.tnemhsinotsa ni tuhs deppans swaj ym dna
”?taeh ni llits I mA“ ”?seY“
’nihtuN” fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT  .tfel
”.em rof rac a ekam ll’uoy tuoba woH
.deen ruoy leef nac I  !ti timda
,hcuot sih fo noitapicitna ni deretsulf-revef gnihctiwt enim fo sdlof elamef wen egnarts esoht
thguoht eht ta em hguorht dehsalf tsul toH
”.oot trap taht rebmemer I
,deyaws dna swap dnih ym no pu esor I
degnahcnu em tfel wolg ehT
”.lla retfa uoy yrram ll’I eb dluoC
.toh gnikoms nmad er’ew dna ’,evoL yppuP‘ ro
.taht ot was su evoba sthgil yrucrem thgirb hsraH
eerf deppils eugnot siH
.demrofsnart gnieb fo tcepsorp eht ta deifirret saw sivlE leef dluoc I
,moT deksa dna yawa detsiwt I
.lla ti fo ssenillis eht ta gnilggig-lworg
dna retsis ruoy s’ehS  !od I seY  !sey …rE“
,hcuot sih ta ecar ot nageb traeh ym dna
gnislup dekcol seidob
.thgir ton saw gnihtemoS
!god a llits dnA“
.plehw ykcoC  !fpmuH ”!GIG a si sihT
.em edisni tfos werg tonk sih dna deredduhs sivlE
.esruoc fo ,suoregnad saw tI
tub ,oot ynroh m’I
”?eb esoht dluow sredro hcihw dnA“
.yb esolc etiuq dna tnelis tsomla
etercnoc deniats-tsur eht no em erofeB
?gnikniht I saw tahw tuB
.god a llitS  .nmaD .elzzum
…wap tnorf eno htiw troppus rof sivlE ot tuo gnihcaer ,ylidaetsnu
,detcerid sA“
eseht piks nac uoy
,ti desaeler I dna tes saw ekarb gnikrap ehT
,evitcerid ruoy fo strap lla tnemelpmi regnol on nac I dna degnahc evah sretemaraP“
.nac uoy fi ,su evigrof esaelp
.ereh regnad ni er’eW  .t’nac ew
!ma I esruoc fO“ ,dedda dna
,drawkcab elzzum ym dekorts dna sgel ruof ot esor I
.neeb dah I sa em fo seiromem pu gnignirb rehtegot
”.reggirt launam ym etavitca dna
.em ot ti dewohs dna egdab DI na tuo thguorb eH
deppiy sivlE dna yoj ni pu deppans liat siH
”.niaga reggirt launam ym etavitca dna ,ria raelc otni
?meht fo erac ekat gniog I saw htraE no woH  ?truh yeht dluoW
”?emit siht enod uoy evah tahW“ ”?seY“
”.wonk’y ,god ’nuoh a tub ’nihtun t’nia I
”?emit siht gnorw s’tahW“
”.seulb pilf-liat toh-taeh eht tog eW“
dnalecarG edistuo gniksub god-dnuoh ytsurt sih dna naicisum teerts a ,emiT tsaL
.oot llits dleh dna sredro ym koot sivlE rednow a rof dna
denrut ew reirrab eht tA
.ediw ti gniworht dna rood s’revird eht rof gnipael
,elyts-wen lla erew sllib ehT
”.dluoc gnikcuf I sredro ruoy fo esoht detnemelpmi evah I
…nottub noitavitca eht revo wap eno desnet eH
.em no kcab dehctal thgil ehT
…ekil ro gniraew er’uoy emutsoc a taht si
?kniht uoy od tahW  ?lleW“
”.tca ruoy ekil yeht epoH
.thgir ti teg t’nac klat-dnim nevE
!yrros os m’I riS“
.demrifnoc draug dnoces eht ”,sgoD  .haeY“
.od ot desoppus er’yeht tahw ksa ot rosivrepus a gninohp s’yoreL kniht I  .etunim a nI“
.esle gnihtemos tuoba klat s’teL  .I od oS  .haeY“
.tfel nrut dna edacirrab dnoces eht ot thgiarts eunitnoc tsuj uoY
.noitseuq rehtona ksa ot egaruoc rehtag ot gniyrt saw eh ekil
”?elbuort ni teg I lliw yenom siht dneps ot yrt I fI
…dna tols pu-mraw ytpme na dna stseug PIV fo lluf moor a sah eh woN
.taes kcab eht ni esactius a dnif ll’uoY“
delrans sivlE ”—erofereht
”.won thgir taht od ll’ew seye ym fo tuo thgilhsalf taht teg uoy fI“
…ruo fo eno uoy erA“ ,deksa eH
?gnos rehtona pu ekam ew tuoba woH
?tuoba no gniog uoy era tahW“ ”.gnieb-llew rieht ot latnemirted yaw yna ni metsys evitcudorper ruoy yfidom ot dezirohtua ton ma I
,em edisni gnisaeler mih tlef I
…dloheb ot nepo sdileye ym deppans I
,drohc a demmurts I
.ksat eht ot etauqeda etiuq sdnah-wap deregnif-trohs ym gnidnif
flesym dleh I ”.ecnahc a flah nevig su toohs lliw nem esehT
…tub retsis ym evol I  !nmaD“ dias eh
,deil I ”,sey …rE“ ”?remrofrep A“  .em
.gniht gnivil a saw swap ym ni ratiug eht ekil
sdrow rehtruf tuohtiW
”!kcab gnimoc era sdraug ehT
.taht naht retteb devresed ohw god a
ereh morf yawa skcart ekam ll’I esimorp I su esaeler yeht sa noos sA
…rebmemer t’nod I …rO
.yawa pils mrof namuh ym fo sthguoht gnittel
.erif fo enil eht ni gnihcuorc flesym dehcnuh I dna
!gniklat taeh eht saw sihT
…ttub-hctib eht tog I …rrhA
”?snalp evitcaorp revelc dna sretspmud tuoba gniyas erew uoy taht saw tahW“ ,ti deksa dna
.god ecivres ym s’eH  .ereh ,sivlE s’ereht lleW“
.tnemeticxe delwoj-yvaeh ni wol gnillol eugnot dna maelga seye
…ekil laeR“ ”.laer s’tI“
…fo ecneidua a erofeb mrofrep ot ecnahc A  !enigamI
,leehw eht nopu sdnah-wap ,sselnoitom
ZZAK .nottub gnirif eht desserp dna
.oot enog saw thgil s’nus eht dna
.enips ym pu yaw rieht lwarc ot htrof tsrub erusaelp fo skraps deretsulc dna
,citamsirahc dna detnelat
?leef I siht s'tahW“
!eruS  ?seulb pilf liaT“
”.senomroh fo stoL“
sretspmud eht fo eno ta em mia uoy fi etartsnomed lliw I
.taht tuob‘ drow a dias eno oN
!hhgrrrraraH“ ”.em deksa reven uoY“
edisa elzzum reifirgomsnart eht denrut I
niaga god ym decnuob-pih I
.god doog a er’uoy—sivlE“
?gniyas I ma tahW  !oN“
.dedulcnoc tsal ta draug eno ”!sgod er’yehT“
”?renepo na rof ’seulB pilF liaT‘ ffo llup dluoc ew esoppus uoy oD
.niaga siht yrt …nac ew yad rehto emos ebyaM
?em tuoba gnihtyna rebmemer uoy oD“ deksa sivlE
dniheb taes eht no ratiug-reifirgomsnart eht deye eH  ”?stseug laiceps
”.snoitcaretni erutuf ni yldneirf-resu erom emoceb dna flesym tpada ot evirts lliw I tub gnimmargorp eroc ym retla tonnac I
,nwod rehtruf ylevitcudes yaw sih krow ot ti denodnaba neht trap taht derolpxe eh sa
…tnemilpmoc a sa ylerup siht naem I dna ewa ni m’I
!taht gniyas pots sivlE“ ”.ssoB ,yrroS“
dias tsal ta dna ,detatiseh I
,doog s’ehs fi yawyna egats no reh tup thgim eh tub ,llibyalp eht no stca yggod yna evah t’nod yeht syas eH
.mih nettib dah sdrow ym fi sa ,em morf yawa decniw dna tuhs seye sih dehcnip sivlE
rood nwo sih revo yltaen gnarps sivlE elihw leehw eht dniheb deppils dna
.erom gniod morf mih gnitneverp dna ydaerla nellows-flah tonk sih ,yaw-trap ylno tub
.hgual ot nageb eh neht
gnipirts eulb niht htiw etihw-lraep saw tnemurtsni ehT
.srebmun laires gnirapmoc ,rehtona detcepsni I
!deedni laiceps erew yeht dworc taht morf erew yggiZ dna groZ fI  .stseug laiceps
.dewolla I ”,ecin rehtar …si sihT“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
yrtne tsrif sih morf tub
.raeg otni dribrednuhT deifirgomsnart ym desae dna leehw eht dniheb noitats koot neht
.won egnahc ot ydaer si ssoB yM  !reifirgomsnarT“
,deriuqni eh tsal tA
gniyas ylmrif ti deson dna reifirgomsnart detcelgen ruo ot deliat-das delffuhs eH
mih ot thguoht I
”?trihs naiiawaH a ni sivlE gnilennahc eissaL yb devomnu eb nac ohW“
.tnemilpmoc ruoy rof uoy knahT“
em dlot dna eerf dellup eH
?niaga ecnahc siht evah d’ew fi yas dluoc ohw
”.won reggirt launam ym etavitca esaelP  .evitamriffA“
,daetsni ,ekarb eht no wap ym tes yltneg I
?em yrram uoy lliw ssoB“ ”?tahW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.og I reverehw em htiw semoC  .raer ym srevoc eH
.emit on gnitsaw ,ti htaeneb ylregae
.erif fo enil eht ni flesym decalp I dna
?gniyas uoy era tahw sivlE“ ”—dna ,seippup eht dna ,uoy fo erac doog ekat ll’I
,em tsniaga resolc elzzum sih desserp sivlE dna kcub ot nageb spih yM
…suretu ruoy ni avo dezilitref owt evah uoy tneserp tA
deplehw er’yeht litnU
,dedda eh emit a retfA
,ladepiB“ .dednamed I
.sterf eht krow ot trohs oot eb dluow sregnif-wap ym gniwonk
,won liat ot liat tub
”0.2 etoyoC weN“
,seldnub talf thgit ni
.sdrohc thgir eht mrof em pleh ot em tsniaga gnisserp dna gnitfil
.tnemtnioppasid god-gnah ni gnipoord liat dna srae
”.dnammoc raelc a timbus esaelP
ylihtoot delims dna srae ym pu dekrep I
”.ycnangerp ruoy gnitanimret diova ot yrassecen saw tI“
”?uoy ekil srehto …ereht erA“
taeh eht tog eW“
.ekil uoy yenom hsac eht lla ezisehtnys nac I tub
.aedi on evah I sthgilhsalf eht dedeen neve yeht yhw hguoht
.niarb gnilhtrae evitimirp ym fo noitalume didnelps ruoy rof uoy knahT  !tnellecxE“ ”.oN“
sehcnuah ruo no kcab tas dna dehgual-piy dna delzzun-eson eW
”?thgir ti teg I diD
,tuo ekam t’ndluoc I gnihtemos derettum em ediseb draug ehT
!nac uoy esruoc fO“
…tnangerp reh tog uoy …ew …I
,neht liat nwo ym thguac dna
?em yrram t’now uoy erus uoy erA
,taes regnessap eht ot revo deppoh eh dna
.dnuorg eht tih tahw saw ratiug retsacotartS egatniv a
.ma’aM sey …rE“ ”?hguone taht t’nsI
”—dna ecalp efas a su dnif dna
,em ta gnikniht sivlE saw tahT
.ffits esrohwas ylsselpleh nezorf sgel dnih ym
”?ffuts dna senomroh dna yregrus
.wol daeh ym deppid dna
.pirg ym nihtiw hprom dna ehtirw ot ti gnisuac
dna gnoledis mih deye I
—dna flesti deriaper pihc llams a sa
”.dnim reveN“ ”—ot ytiliba ym dnoyeb raf era serutluc evitimirp fo smotsuc yratenom yrotcidartnoc dna xelpmoc ehT
eloh liat ym dehsurb sreksihw tfoS
niorg ym ot wap-dnah a desserp I  ”?god a llits yhW
”—tsuj erew uoy thguoht eW
?namuh eb ot tnaw uoY
egdolsid ot elbissopmi
.reggirt eht desserp dna
.dnim ym morf seippup dna ycnangerp fo thguoht eht tup ot gniyrt ,delworg I
.nwod yldas gnipoord liat htiw em rof sselnoitom doots ohw ,sivlE ta ti demia dna nug yar eht pu dekcip I
ma’aM“ ”.esoppus I ,od lliw ma’aM“  .dehgis I
.yoreL dias ”!tiaW“ ”…lleW“
.gniyas saw moT ekil ,reirrab dnoces eht ta tfel nrut neht daeha thgiartS“
”!desufnoc os m'I ?laer eb ti naC
,mih tsniaga thgit-elbmert em deppirg sivlE dna spmuh gnivird-peed wef A
.ekoms etteragic fo knits neddus eht ot gnizeens-flah delkcit eson ym neht
”!ssoB ,etad a flesruoy tog ev’uoY  !thgirlA“
?tey enod ew erA  .ynnuf yreV“
”?od ot gniog uoy era tahW“
efil ot dezalb thgilhsalf dnoces A
…no gnikaens neht kcen sih nwod ylhtooms gnidils
,seohs delos-tfoS
”.god a yats ot tnaw uoY
.wonk’y ,tca ssalc a tog eW  !uoy etib
.eissaL yllaicepsE
.esnes doog ym no gnitnuoc saw sivlE  .nmaD
.mih ot dekcilf thgilhsalf eht dna delworg sivlE em ediseB
.won kcuts er'ew ,raed hO“ ”!esufer t'nac I smees ti won reffo ruoy pu kooT“ ”.seulb pilf-liat toh-taeh eht tog eW“
!llits dloh dna pu tuhS  !sivlE“ mih dlot I
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
!enil eht no si sremmuS .rM“
…yas uoy diD  .tiaW“
…dna kool ot daeh ym detsiwt I
…pilf liat eht tog I
,detsaob I ”!lliw yeht esruoc fO“
.yaw noitalupoc eninac deronoh-emit eht ni
.ssuf hcum tuohtiw ereh fo tuo eb dluohs ew os ,su peek ot sdnuorg on evah yeht dna ,won sPIV er’eW
deppiy I dna niaga nwod desserp wap siH
…dna uoy ffo sehtolc yllis esoht teg ot tiaw t’naC
drawpu nug-yar eht demia I
,htiw krow ot gnitartsurf dna
,krowten gniknab s’tenalp ruoy gnitalupinam morf em tneverp slocotorp ytefas yM“
.seiromem ruo neve …reifirgomsnart ,yenom ,rac  :gnihtyreve kcab ekat dna macs ruo hguorht ees d’yeht ton sa ekiL
”.ti yebo ot dezirohtua ton ma I tub ,raelc si dnammoc ruoY“
.noisserpxe tnedifnoc yltneconni na dekaf dna rehtegot flesym dellup neht
.won uoy rof edivorp yam I ecivres rehtona stseggus noitalume yM
,won pal ym nopu lluf gnittis saw sivlE
?uoy od ,namuh eb ot tnaw yllaer t’nod uoy dnA“ ”.nac I yaw yna
ria eht ta gnipmuh yllacitnarf
.iel dihcro etaciled ym fo dragersid sselerac ni em tsniaga syawedis flah gninael
,dedneffo eb t’nod esaelp
…dna eromyna mih gnitnaw eb t’ndluow I kcab redneg dna ydob dlo ym dah I fI
.dessap ylkciuq sgnileef esoht dna emit siht tegrat eht ton saw I tub
elbitrevnoc dribrednuhT eno ytxis neetenin
.ezeens delfits a ekil erom saw ti os dnuos eht kcab dekohc tub kcohs ni deppiy sivlE
.gnihcaorppa spetstoof draeh I dna
”—dna daeha gnillac s’yoreL
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
”…seulb pilf liat toh-taeh eht
.trap taht htiw tol a depleh sivlE
.truh fo dlrow a ni sevlesmeht dnif nac meht pleh ot namuh a tuohtiw sgod
,em tsniaga resolc delggiw dna wol daeh sih deppils god dnuoh yM
.sgnileef eurt dessessop ti fi sa ,yaw ykaens
”?ffuts dna emils dna doolb ni derevoc lla tuo emoc taht dnik ehT
em ssorca tfos-rehtils
tpeC‘  .rof tuo eye na gnipeek eb ot desoppus er’ew syarts esoht ekil tsuj ,god ’nuoh a ’na eilloc A“
.ti ediseb enorp flesmih delttes dna reifirgomsnart detcelgen ruo ot revo knuls eh
,su dniheb sdraug ytiruces desumeb fo riap eht ot ,kcab dekool I
levon retskcirt lacigam siH
sa em ot desrap ylraelc
.htob fo tros ro …dnah ro
.emit emas eht ta sniarb owt htiw gnikniht ekil
swaperof sih neewteb ti thguac eH
deilper ecived eht dna ,delrans I
…edisni tsurht dna edaps ym dnuof eH
.etalp esnecil eht rof tpecxE
.dekrab I ”!reifirgomsnarT“
.ereht avluv hctib a fo dnuom evitisnes tfos eht tlef dna
”.ylefas ti dneps nac I em llet tsuJ
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.edis ym yb godnroh detiecnoc gnitnap eht eht ot revo neht
!suolucidir s’tahT  ?ycnangerP“
dnuora delruc eH
gniggard saw eugnot tew ediw sih neht
.ssoB ,uoy htiw eb ot tnaw I“
.hcuot hguor-kcils eht htiw dam em gnivird dna gnisuor—
,em ta thguoht dna
”?dnim ni mrof namuh cificeps a evah uoy oD  .evitamriffA“
.erom rof deen ni gnireviuq em deldnik dna nemes tneps sih yawa deppal eh sa
?gniyas uoy era tahW  !sivlE“
.noitseuq a s’ti ,redro na ton s’tahT“
,sretsknarp neddih fo hcraes ni tuoba ti devaw dna em ffo thgil sih koot eH
,ereh mrof yawa efas teg ot detnaw uoy thguoht I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”?og dluohs ew su gnillet uoy erew yaw hcihW
”.ylefas ti dneps nac uoY“
ezis lluf ot sdnoces ni dellews tonk siH
.em ediseb taes regnessap tnorf eht ni flesmih dehcrep dna
.gniht a egnahc t’nod ti
.won thgir degnahc uoy teg ll’ew …yrros os m’I
:iel dihcro na dnA
.elbmesne naiiawaH elttil ’nilrad s’eilloc ruo rof
,otni naicisum eht mrofsnart ot reifirgomsnart etelosbo na desu dna
mih pleh ot kcab dne dnih ym dehcnuh I dna noitartsurf ni gnikaeuqs-repmihw em dehcnelc eH
”goD ’nuoH a tub ’nihtuN“
swaperof sih neewteb nug yar eht thguac sivlE
,leef eht teg ot tsuj ,syawyna meht deirT
.raeg fo tuo detfihs dna
nosaer fo elkcirt A  ”…rO
!seippup ruoy gniyrrac m’I sivlE“
.niarb gnilhtrae evitimirp ym rof noitseuq a peed oot ,dnim reven ,dnim reveN  !ti morf tuo gnimoc dnuos cirtcele na saw tahT
”?tnaw yllaer uoy od tahw ,sivlE“
tuo dehcaer draug ehT
”?seippup epyt tnangerp-em-tog-god-niarb-rof-sllab-gnikcuf-yM“
”?tceted nac elpoep ym swalf yna ereht erA  ”.seY“
.oot gub eht sah sivlE
”?srebmun laires tnereffid evah lla yeht oD“
”?yrruh a ni ew erA“ rumrum dna
.sladep eht no swap dnih ym dna
.esruoc fo ,detaehc htob eW
,thgirlA“ dias eh eciov reraelc a nI
,neht dna esuap trohS
tiw s’lertnim eht dootsrednusim ohw ,sneila owt deretnuocne
”?won rof hguone taht sI
.rac wen ym fo sroloc eht dehctam yltcaxe ti fo eulb dna etihw eht dna
.uoy tespu ot naem t’ndiD  .yug yrroS“ ”.esle
.noitseuq ruoy ot rewsna elbailer a evig tonnac I tub yrros ma I“
.eviecrep dluoc I walf on dewohs srekcits noitartsiger etad-ot-pu eht dna
!em dniheb dnatS  !sivlE“ derepsihw I
”?niaga uoy etam em tel dna—“
.gnisiurb a depacse ylerab selcitset sih dna pal ym ffo flah nworht saw eh os ,sih fo pmur ynob gums taht tsniaga pu drah spih ym dekcor dna detrons I
”.nevigrof er’uoY  .dnim reveN“
”.detpecca redrO“ ”!od esaelP“
”?taht tuoba sthguoht yna evah uoy oD  ?sivlE …“
gnisir xamilc a tlef I
sdileye tuhs-dehcnip hguorht thgirb dewolg erif neerG !GNIZZ-
”…ekil uoy fi …won ereht kcab pu uoy naelc nac I …ssoB“ em dlot eH
”.seulb pilf-liat toh-taeh eht tog eW“ ”?niaga ereh gnimoc eb uoy lliW“ ”?eman ruoy s'tahW
emit trohs dliw a rehtegot deniarts eW
…ni sa seippuP  ?seippup
,ekil uoy tahw yaS  .spahrep ,hE“
.od lliw sihT  .sey …rE“
.rethgil etteragic a rof deen etaidemmi on dah I
dednammoc ew rehtegoT
,repeed ,rekciuq dekcilf eugnot siH
”…ro …ris em esucxE“ dias eH
yltfos mih deggeb dna esolc delggiw I
.od ot krow tog ew dna ytud no er’eW
2 fo 2 traP ,rednebraE yb
”!uoy fo hctib tsenoh na ekam ll’I dna drow eht evig tsuJ
.ssergorp ni llits saw noitaluvo tub derb neeb d’uoY  .seY“
.rehtegot dekeirhs ylsseleciov ew ”!gig A“
em demlehwrevo noitatpmet teewS  ”.on …“
,niaga dekorts eugnot siH
.eilloc elamef a ,eissaL ,llew
,leehw gnireets eht gnikrow swap tnorf ym deciton ylurt emit tsrif eht rof dna esolc dereep draug ehT
”—wolla snoitaluger sa mrof ni namuh ot esolc sa
.reh evol lliw dworc ehT
,noitartnecnoc ni pu gnikrep srae eilloc dekcut-pit htob
,dedeen kcip ratiug on
pal ym ssorca ylevissessop flesmih delggiw sivlE
,rae gnipoord eno ssik-kcil ot revo denael I
.lliw uoy wonk uoy ,dnuora emoc ll’uoY  .trats a s’tI“
.draveluob eht no kcab pu dne ll’uoy ro nrut eht ssim t’noD
”.gnorw seog esle gnihtemos erofeb niaga namuh em ekam dna dessucof yats ot deen ew …I
meht htiw uoy pleh ll’I dnA
.nwo sih sa ti gnirahs
.meht wollof em pleh ot enituorbus noitalume na detaerc dna senilediug wen ym dezilanretni evah I“
!tpecca I  !thgirlA“
…dna niarb ym hguorht ylevitcudes gnillor gnikamevol ruo fo fo tnecs knar eht ,ylpeed ria pmad eht deffins I …dnA  !god a saw eh
,rehtegot doots ew detacixotnI
.thguoht lla yawa gnippirts
.tol eht ta uoy teem lliw draug rehtonA
”?su rof taht od uoy naC  !reifirgomsnarT
!oN  ?lagel ti sI
”.gniht siht tsurt t’nod llits I
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.yoj ylno ym si ecivreS“
?seippup ydob-ym-edisni-serutaerc-elttil-gnilggiw
.ssertsid uoy esuac ot dnetni ton did I tub
.raeg otni dribrednuhT eht tfihs ot ytinutroppo eht koot I dna
deppiy I dna niarb deirf-taeh ym otni dezoo
!em sevol yllaer god taht tub
.retal uoy kcuf ll’I ,hE“ ”—ebyam neht dna
,llew sa gnitaralihxe tey ypeerC
.efil ot yltnatsni enigne evissam eht gniknarc
!lliw uoy wonk I  .meht tuoba dnim ruoy egnahc ll’uoy tub
,em morf nwod deppets dna
?gniklat taeh eht tsuj ton s’ti eruS
ynorhcnys deknil ni gnihctiwt llits su fo htob
mhtyhr ydaeh a pu gnidliub ,niaga neht
”…rood kcab ruoy 'nuor ffins nac I lleW“
owt…dna yaw siht kcuts eb d’I dna reifirgomsnart eht esol dluoc eW
”?deecorp ot em rof hsiw uoy oD
,taorht a fo gniraelc eht ,hguoc a draeh I
.detalucric neeb reven dah yeht ekil gnikool
—dna ,teews dna ,htooms tuo emac ti dna
”!nac gnikcuf uoy tahw tnemelpmi dna parc eht tuC“
.ti no gnittis saw I hguoht neve mih rof knik ot tseb sti gniyrt liat ym
.tlef I naht ecnedifnoc erom raf gnitcejorp
.kcul doog …re …a evaH
”?won og ew naC  ?ssoB“ deldeehw eH
.xes god tew fo amora war gnitacixotni eht ni gnihtaerb ,gnillol seugnot
esimorp ym etipsed
.iiawaH eulB rof tes gnimlif eht ffo thgiarts gnimees elyts ukah etihw elap tnagele
”!oot em rof gniloord er’uoY
.evitcaoidar ylbissop etiuq dna ,evitpecer ,evitcudes s’ehS
”.doirep noitatseg eritne rieht hguorht selam tpecca lliw sehctib emoS
,deggurhs yeht tsal ta tub sivlE ta decaf-nezorf gnirats erew sdraug ehT
.pirts ytiruces cihpargoloh gnikool-eniuneg yrev a fo hsalf psirc raelc eht dna elims-flah gniwonk s’nilknarF nimajneB devresbo dna
,wen dellems neve ,wen dnarb dekool rac eht tuoba gnihtyreve dna
,htgnel ta detcepsni erew ew dna
,em hguorht dna dnuora degrus ssenthgirb gnimmurht neerG !KCAZZ-
tilc eninac ym dnuora delruc dna dnuof sih fo eugnot yzarc taht sa
.tolp llef ym dedneherpmoc eh erofeb esab liat sih barg-pin ylyls ot
.bonk gnorw eht saw ti tub ,bonk a dellup dna hctiws thgildaeh eht rof tuoba dehcraes I
.oot mih koot msagro derahs ruo sa nemes fo stej llams tuo gnitriuqs dna
!boj a teg ll’I dna namuh em ekam nac uoY
!gig a saw ti tuB
!pop—emit siht dna
taes kcab eht ni ratiug-reifirgomsnart ym dessot I
”!tnangerp m’I dias uoY  ?taeh ni llits I ma yhW“ ”.evitamriffA“
.oot rac eht dna ,ereh fo tuo sgod eseht teG
.deniwtretni ylbanoinapmoc sliat ruo dna
.sutats ycnangerp fo sseldrager ,syad lareves tsal staeh eninac lamroN“
?yas I nac tahw ;reniatretne na m’I
oot redrah nwod tib I dna noitasnes eht ta gnilgnit dehtirw
”!pih eht ta denioj er’ew ekil sleef ti rehtegot pu deit os er’ew semitemoS
niaga demmurts I
.truh tsomla ti litnu nwod hteet sih dnuorg eh sa yltfos gnilworg
,ti denepo dna taes kcab eht ni esactius a dnuof I
srae ym dekcut I ylkeeM
.eralg thgil yrucrem hsrah eht ni elprup detnit sroloc eurt eht
,gniK eht dna eissaL su llac nac eh sremmuS .rM lleT“
.hguone s’hguone tub emit siht doog em tog syug uoy
pirg sih dexaler sivlE neht
.bmud-yzarc dna suoregnaD
!tols ym dnuof uoY  .thguac era sgel yM“ ”.seulb pilf-liat toh-
”.og uoy tel dna flesym ot flesym peek ll’I
…esrow ro dab ro doog roF
taeh ni uoy tup ot evitcerid s’noinapmoc ruoY“
.tiaw dluoc noitacifirgomsnarT