I tub ,ssoB ,enihcam eht ta gnikniht uoy tlef I“
”,gnilf a stnaw tsuj eH
?esaelp ,emit eht evah uoy od tub
,drawrof gnivird spih sih fo egnul dliw eht tlef I
ot pu elzzum worran ym gnippils ,dehgual I ”,ssuf uoy t’nod yppuP“
.ssarg denrub-kcalb fo hctap elttil sti ni reifirgomsnart eht dna
”.wonk uoy tel ot tsrif eht eb ll’I segnahc taht fI
.gnorw yrev ,ereh gnorw gnihtemoS
”!seiromem sti epiw ot tegrof t’nod dnA“
,I dna sivlE ,htob su desacne wolg-erif gniremmihs neerG  .reggirt eht— .esnefed ym ot yltnailav gnipael dna sredro gnirongi ,sivlE deyab ”!wow-wow--wworH“ ,dna delley I ”!kcab teg
iK“ .yad eht fo taeh eht morf won wol gnilgnad dna yvaeh dna pmulp
,rettam ot ton hguone esolc ro ,htaed ym naem dluow tahT
…dna thgir gnikrow ton sgeL
,reifirgomsnart eht pu rehtag ylluferac ot swaj ym detrap dna
.enituor noitanosrepmi sivlE god-nam taebffo ruo ot gnimoclew erom evorp dluow srab nwotnwod eht ebyaM
erusaelp sselpleh ni ffits dezies sgel yM  ”!huh-
,oot nellows saw avluv eninac depahs-y ym nwod rehtruF
dna wol daeh sih gnuh sivlE
.deviecer I esnopser eht rof deraperpnu saw I llits tub
”…tfird ym hctac uoy fi ,ecnatsissa elbignat fo tib a tuohtiw llet ot das oot
.evah thgim eilloc detaoc hguor a ekil …
!yllausac oot raf ssenisub noitamrofsnart siht gnikat m’I
!ecaf-owt a si god A“
,evah sgod yaw yllis taht ni rehto eht ot dne eno morf em gnipmub-ffins yllufeelg saw eh dna ylsuoiruf gniggaw saw liat sih neht
.syawyna ecin tlef stnemevom gnigguh dna gnitsurht-pih eht tub ,htiw mih ekop yledur ot sgel ym neewteb kcoc gnibborht oN
”.ereht ni er’yeht fi tuo me‘ evird ll’sihT
.roivaheb rieht ni ecnedifnoc llitsni ot tey gnihton nees d’I dna
?ti s’tahT  ?yllaeR“
,rae ym leef uoy t’nod hO
rellams em edam dah noitamrofsnart yM
,mih htiw deredduhs-elgnit dna kcen ’sivlE nwod delbbin I  .etunim a nI
!ti/ehs/eh dnik sgniteerG“
?gniyas I ma tahW  !parC
,ti yb decnartne ,noitasnes eht gnihsiler
htuoy reh ni saw ehs sa ytterp os ton
.deciton dah sivlE  .puY
!em hguorht dellor noitasnes gniggut-tonk neddus taht woH
.evah sgod elam yaw evislupmoc egnarts taht ni em morf nwod deppets neht dna tegdif ot nageb sivlE
peed hsrah gnitnap
.dnammoc ym ta devom sgel eht niaga ecno dna ,niaga dehsarht I
”!kcab em egnahC“ deredro dna
,tnelis werg sivlE
?foorpretaw reifirgomsnart eht saW .su gnidulcnI
,ti leef dluoc I ,em rof gninrub saw sivlE
”!ssshts-ssss-eeercS“  .tsehc sih ot esolc dnah neila dehcnelc-thgit a degguh dna reifirgomsnart eht nwod werht yggiZ  !KAZ-aarrK —a ti saw—eb dluohs eson ym erehw—gniht nat gnol yrruf taht dnA
”?kcehc ot dnuora me‘ evohs annog uoY
.shgiht ym dnuora thgit gnikooh sgelerof sih
.dnammoc ruoy tnemelpmi ot secruoser eht ssessop yltnerruc ton od I tub yrros ma I
tsehc ym tsniaga pu gnisserp
,edis ym yb esolc sivlE
edolpxe ro em etucortcele dluow ti elihw eht lla gniraef
”.kcab ti egnahc ll’I
…fo dnik tsuj gnihtolc dna secaf dna riaH
”.taeh otni uoy tup ot em deredro noinapmoc ruoY“
.sdnah namuh fo psarg eht ot detiusnu etiuq pirg detsiwt yglub a dna
?won thgir taht no gnikrow eb I t’ndluohs …dnA
.noitcivnoc on deirrac enot sih tub ,em demrofni groZ ”,gniyl er’uoY“
.noitanretsnoc ni daeh ym ot talf gnisserp srae ym tlef dna yltfos denihw I  !tsoL
.oot gnilgnit erew yehT  .selppin ym dnA
…drow retteb a fo kcal rof eh htiw og ot tseb
?si taht ,dnammoc noitacifirgomsnart namuh-ot-god reporp A
.lortnoc rednu ti peek ot elba eb dluohs I ;melborp a toN
.hsinif ssolg ydnac nosmirc dedaf eht niats t’ndluow I os
,ylper kciuq ni derepsihw god dnuoh ym ”?uoy taht si ssoB“
,ereht dna ereh dehsalps yarps elzzon eht elihw rehtegot gnivomnu dna tnelis dehcuorc I dna sivlE
?yawyna ,won tfel evah I did fles dlo ym fo hcum woH
”—erofeb kcab ti egnahc ,kciuQ
thgirb dehsalf ssenyarg eht neht dna
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
,peed gnitrups nemes sih fo kcohs citatsce gnihctiwt eht dna sbaj-yoj gnikcub trohs sih tlef ,oot ydob nwo ym htiw esaeler sih tlef I .em otnI
,em no nwod gnimoc saw thgiew sih nehw flesym decarb I dah yldraH
.evitamriffA“ ”?gnihtemos ro edom ycavirp ni ew erA
,demialcorp dna mra eerf ym htiw yllacirtaeht derutseg I  .egatnom-gum-ylgu-god-dnuoh yllis a otni serutaef derruf-yarg-leets denniks-esool sih gnihcnurcs dna mra ym ni daeh sih gnipmalc ,neht
sunim skcubecaps noillim evif ytriht rof laiceps ecnaraelc nwod-kram no elbaliava yltnerruc ma I
.ecnelis ot dedaf muh s’reifirgomsnart eht yllaudarg dna
?etelosbo sraey noillizab a ,ekil yeht t’nerA
,enog erew yeht dna dedaf dna
,ereht ti detser dna nottub gnirif eht revo waperof eno decalp I
yllacimhtyhr gnihctiwt llits htob
?elbbab gnisitrevda cihtapelet hcet-hgih fo tros emos ti saW
”…nuh ,em ’lot enod ammom yM“ deretnuoc dna
,edis eno ot dekcoc daeh
.noitacifirgomsnart sih ecnis mih fo weiv dne-dnih raelc tsrif ym ta tnemhsinotsa ni depag swaj ym dna
!dnasuohT ruoF kraM ledom tsewen s’niarborciM
,dneirf ym ,elat das ,das a s’tI“
,htob su deifirgomsnart dna dam tog yeht desufer ew nehw dna tcartnoc reporp a tuohtiw su drocer ot detnaw yehT“  .deerga I
,meht fo owt erew erehT  .ffo
,ti gnola nwod dettort-kluks ylkciuq dna yella ecivres a nopu emac eW
derettum dna dnuora dekool
.tnorf eht ssorca srettel kcolb ni ”KCOR ESUOHLIAJ“ sdrow eht htiw noitanimoba parc-tsiruot retseylop depirts-kcalB  .tah a dnA
.pots a ot delgrug tsal ta dna
,evitisnes dna knip osla
”?yaw siht yats ot gniog uoy erA  !oot ,hctib etuC
htob su deifirgomsnart ohw srelggums ytreporp lautcelletni nairodnA fo gnag a fo luofa nar ew lit‘ elbbik elbbirT-eht-fo-etsaT muimerp dna eniwdoolb enif saw lla
,sredluohs sih dehcnuh ,ylsuovren ria eht deffins dna
derettum yggiZ  ”,erus ,haey ,haeY“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.saw ti tahw tsuj yas t’ndluoc
,rae ym dniheb ,drawkcab ylwols elzzum tnulb sih dekrow sivlE elihw
.xamilc eninac gniogno lufssilb ni
dna gniyalp deunitnoc I elihw sremocwen eht ta deralg dna tuhs slwoj sih deppans sivlE
”.flesruoy nialpxe esaelP
dna ruf etihw was dna nwod dekool I
”!god a otni flesruoy nrut dluoc uoy wenk reven I  ?truh uoy erA
?yelserP .rM uoy llac I dluohs ro—
.em ta ti demia dna
”?sretspmud esoht dniheb
dna niaga gnihsarht ,delrans I
.dehcuot eb ot deen etarepsed eht htiw gnihctiwt-elgnit dnuom hctib ym dna
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”!delbbarfrek …tsuj ti dna eldoodiralop eht esrever ot deirt I  !wonk t’nod I“
segnahc derised eht ezilausiv ylraelc ot mih tcerid esaelP
.tae ot hguone doog dna elam-yknuf dna hciR
.oot selbbin eht gnileef yaw egnarts emos ni
tsul htiw erifa ecno ta lla dnim ym
gniht sih htiw kcuts steG“
:leips selas dennac sti nageb ti niaga ecno dna
”—saw I tluaf ym ton s’tI
mih rof llits doots I
—dna yas ot deirt I ”?sivlE“
tsal ta egufer gnidnif
.dehctaw I sa flesti denethgiarts tub
tub niatrecnu dna drawkwA
kcab dekrej sivlE
.biS ,nwod tserC  !thgirla ,thgirlA“ ”—tuohtiw lagel yltcaxe ton
,hcuot ot diarfa
,retaw hcum os ylraen ton gnicudorp ruf trohs sih
.peed-sllab won ereht esolc gnisserp dna
,lanoitidda gniwohs dna
”?riS“  ”—a tub ’nihtun t’nia uoY wwwor-wa
sa kcohs ni de-eerks yggiZ .etiB— ”—
”?oot sivlE htiw etacinummoc uoy naC  !reifirgomsnarT“
.yllacitnarf ti htiw elddif ot nageb dna
?elbbin-rae elttil tneconni na htiw gnorw og uoy nac woH
”!truh tahT“  .dezeehw eh
?gnisserd saw ehs nehw rehtom ruoy no yps dluoc uoy os tesolc moordeb ruoy fo kcab eht ni llawyrd eht hguorht eloh a dehctarcs uoy dlo sraey net erew uoy nehw taht wonk I taht wonk uoy diD
won thgir tub ,ti eganam nac I sa noos sa pmuh ot pmur elitref a evah uoy ees ll’I dna sgnileef ruoy dnatsrednu I
!ti/ehs/eh dnik sgniteerG“
.pukcab rof gnillac fo tnetni eht htiw ylraelc
.llet dluoc I sa raf sa ,god a llits saw I
snif laretal tneculsnart prahs-remmihs htiw etelpmoc
”?uoy ot ecivres fo eb I yam woH
.oot em ni uoy fo emos evah I tub sivlE llits m’I
”goD ’nuoH a tub ’nihtuN“     yojne esaelP
,dluow god elam a ekil pot no debmilc dna
,yarg delacs-elbbep hsilprup dna
shgiht sih deggans I gnihgual-piY
neht ylsuoiruc dekcil-elzzun I …llitS
reporp a sa em ezilausiv ot uoy detnaw I
,oot flesmih koohs dna dewollof ylkciuq sivlE
.raen gniretnuas sdraug ytiruces dnalecarG owt fo spetstoof eht dna
ediskcab ym fo evruc eht tif ot tliub
.melborp on si erehT“
—ekil hcum yrev dekool taht nibbun eulb ypmub a no nwod ylmrif gnizeeuqs saw tigid kciht eno dna
s’niarborciM fo esahcrup ruoy no snoitalutargnoC
,dehtoos eh ”,sgnilhtrae ,su esucxE“
,won resolc gnildis saw groZ
”goD ’nuoH a tub ’nihtuN“
,su ot deneppah gnihtemos …dna
,niorg sih tsniaga thgit gnillup sllab sih tlef
em ta ti mia ot uoy tnaw I
”?tuoba gniklat uoy era
.nosaes ni god elamef A  .em …llew
eslup mih morf tuo gnittej llits mreps eht repeed gniward yltneg
,neila eht nopu ezag elitsoh a denetsaf dna spil sih delruc sivlE ”.yatS
daeh sih gnibbob
,sey ,esool sgod gib fo elpuoc A
,dnim reven tuB  .yot-xes yrruf lanosrep
”!ffwwuarG“ .em wen eht fo lavorppa sih fo ecnedive elyts-god-elam ylgnissarrabme
”!hgrrarG“ ”.ecin llems uoY
.sthguoht ym daer dluoc eh fi sa
,no tnew yaw egnarts a ni xamilc ym tub denruter stiw ym ylwolS  .stnap gnipsar
,dnuos lufrednow ,ratiug eciN
?ton ro uoy yub ot em tnaw uoy oD  !ffpmmH“ ”—erus m’I
—tub toof a htiw tah noitanod ym degdun
”!lla ta dekrow parc fo eceip taht eveileb t’nac I
,hgual ot nageb ylegnarts neht
”!haeyklat-teews nog god A“
”?thgir ,srelggums nairutcrA naem uoY“
,noissimrep sserpxe roirp ruoy htiw ,dna
.devarc won I yaw etamitni erom taht ni mih htiw tcatnoc ekam ot eganam etiuq t’ndluoc …etiuq …t’ndluoc I dna
”?ssoB seY“ .deppiy I ”?payl-
!cissalc a s’gniht sihT  .groZ ,girht a eb t’noD“
”?deneppah tahW
.ti fo wolf gnilkcit etamitni eht yb xamilc nwo ym ot
!saw I yaw eht ot kcaB“
,eb ot desoppus m’I sa em ezilausiv dna
.esruoc fo ,neppah ot gniog ton saw tahT
,nwod god doog a peek t’nac uoy woh
.ereht ti tfel I dna
ruoy ton ,niaga namuh elam
”!tiaW“ detuohs reciffo ehT
”?taht od I od woH  .evird tset eerf a rof tuo uoy ekat ro ,uoy tner rO  !ydaerla uoy yub ot tnaw I
;denrecnoc eb ot deen oN
.gnirraj eb nac noitasrevnoc lamron ot kcab noitisnart eht dna ,esle gnihton fo kniht I yalp I nehW
.sllarevo bib eulb wen-erots sih fo tnorf eht no sniats dratsum dah enO
”?lla ta kcab em egnahc uoy t’naC
.sivlE god gniklat ym dnA
tahW“ ”.etats evitpecer yllauxes a ni uoy ecalp ot segnahc latnem dna lacisyhp detnemelpmi evah I ,detseuqer sA
,redrah tsurht dna denihw sivlE
,egaruoc gnirehtag
.mrof wen ym naht retrohs ylthgils tub reivaeh sivlE
”?esaelp ,edoc ruoy si tahW
.niarb eilloc deifirgomsnart ym desuffus
.eromyna siht ekil me‘ ekam t’nod tsuj yehT
.lla ta namuh deraeppa regnol on ti dleh taht dnah eht ;trap tsal taht rettam oN
fo 1 traP ,rednebraE yb
.gnola evom dna ffo me‘ wolb ot emit
htiw drawpu gniniarts spih ym delruc I
,mih revo gnimoc kool egnarts a
”!godnroh ynroh uoy ,taht ekaT“ deppiy dna
.esoppus I ,eb dluoC“
!doog yllaer s’tahT  !sivlE“
…fo dnik ylterces ot dna …!god a yb
,desufnoc dna dezad hgih ym morf nwod emac I tsal ta tub ,gnol woh erus ton m’I
”.tuo ti tros ot yrt I elihw etunim a em eviG
.won dne dnih ym raen gnitseuq saw eson sih
won tsul htiw gniliob saw doolb yM  .ton sseuG
.ruf ylleb tfos etihw-klim hguorht tuo gnikop selppin evitisnes yletisiuqxe knip nellows fo swor gnidnif
?god a ton er’uoy naem uoy od tahW“ ”!pay-PIY-pay-paY“
hctap kcalb-dehcrocs a no reifirgomsnart dedaolrevo toh-gnikoms a evas tisiv rieht fo ecart on gnivael
.nihs sih gnikcik yb pu mih tuhs dah—groZ—eno rehto eht dna gniklat eno deniats-dratsum eht saw tahT
!tnaem I tahw ton s’tahT  !oN“
!ton s’ti oN“ ”—dna redro gnikrow tcefrep ni s’ti os gniriaper-fles era sledom dnasuohT ruoF kraM
tuob‘ woH“ ”.edih ot ecalp oN  .won ereh ton er’yeht did yeht fI  .haN“
.sthguoht ym sucof ot gnivirts ,dellats I ”,on …hhA“
,emit a rof gnitnap ereht deldduh ew dna reifirgomsnart eht nwod tes I
?uoy t’ndid yhW“ ”.evitamriffA“
.mih dnuof I erehw retlehs lamina eht yb detacsifnoc selcitset sih htiw neve ,saw eh ,sthgif gnikcip syawlA
em gnivig saw eh kool yrgnuh eht morf taht llet ot hguone ysaE
…dna won yb enog eb ot dah sdraug ehT
pmur sih ssorca nihc ym detser I
.ynnuf ton s’taht ssoB“ ”!ffiY“
…retfa detsul dna delgo eb oT
.esac yna ni sselhtrow saw tops eht dna enog-raen saw noonretfa eht ,rettam oN
”—eb ot tnemegduj doog lanoitpecxe ssessop uoy ylraelC
?siht ekil em edisni gnivom gnihtemos evah I nac woH
.em ot tsol etiuq yteltbus fo tfig eht dna
:llird eht wenk dna gnitam sgod nees d’I
.ti nopu nwod dekool dna reifirgomsnart degamad eht ot revo derettot I
.cas-ed-luc yella ecivres elttil yzoc ruo ni tnelis saw lla dna
.rae ym leef uoy t’nod
.diarfanu tub suoituac
!esrevinu ,tuo hctaW
”?taht ekil sciryl ekam ot nrael uoy did nehW
dne dnih sih ni emoh knas hteet eninac prahs
”—emit siht dna reifirgomsnart eht ekat woN
.dne dluow ti woh flesym rof ees ot detnaw
,deniwtretni sliat
,esac ratiug ym dna ,ratiug ym etagitsevni ot edisa denrut dna deggurhs eh neht
!groZ ,emit elttil a em eviG“ derettum eH
.sgod elam yllaicepse dna
ateZ gnillac m’I ro won thgir kcab ti egnahC“ ”—s’taht fi erus ton m’I …rE“
.did ohw god emos fo gnittur lufeelg eht etadommocca ot tliub saw ydob wen yM
,rednu nwod flesym deson ylhguor dna revo deppolf I
deppiy I dna yllufyalp kcab deggut eH
,yawa llup ot flesym decrof I
.sreciffo laicnanif niarborciM yb noitamrifnoc gnidnep detpecca yllanoisivorp neeb sah tub
,repeed ni dehctiwt dna eurt kcurts sivlE sa
?gnihtemos ro tif tsgna na gniworht ro tuo gnisserts eb I t’ndluohS
”.tahw ot kcab yficeps esaelP
ylmrif nwod desserp I neht
ym fi sa ;ti tuoba kniht t’ndid I nehw drah os ton saw tI
.snug yrrac t’nod sgod tub
?did yeht fi meht tsurt ew dluoC
eseht piks nac uoy
.yaw god-elamef elbissop tnatalb tsom eht ni edis eno ot liat ym gnitrilf dna dnuor gnippihw
rethgit werg ssenlluf fo gnileef tahT
”!thgir ton s’tahT“
,eno ekil hcum gnihtemos ro ,nug yar ecaps a tub yenom ton tuo thguorb dna tekcop a ni dehcaer yggiZ  ”!ti od ll’I ,kO“
,fo tros si taht
”!yawa steg ti erofeB  !sggiZ ,kcab ti egnahC“
.skeehc sih ediseb nwod ylpmil gnipoord srae yarg derruf-tevlev sih
.taebtraeh a ni ti no depmuj evah d’ew laed erauqs a su dereffo d’yeht fi yllaeR
”?lliw ruoy tsniaga dna noissimrep tuohtiW“ ”…haey
…ekil derruf-kciht dna etihw dna nat-hsiddeR
,llaw etercnoc eht tsniaga drah desserp pih eno
…flesmih ot segru derevef suorehcel sih peek dluoc sivlE
wwoY“ —neht tsrif ta tegrat ffo
em nihtiw selcsum dehcterts-pmuh
!emit evah t’nod ew giZ“
,eb ot thguo uoy sa uoy ezilausiv ,miA  .ssoB ,ti toG“
tekcop sih morf tcejbo llams a werdhtiw groZ elihw em trofmoc ot dnuora gnippihw dna pirg-
?tnatculer eb ot dneterp tsael ta I t’ndluohS  !won yllaeR
!uoy ta dam ton m’I sivlE“
annog s’eno yarg eht kniht I
!ydaerla nepo era seye stI  !yggiZ—
tsrif ta kcohs a saw retaw dloc ehT
.yelserP sivlE eb ylbissop tonnac taht …tuB“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yegreB leahciM flesmih sllac osla ohw ,rednebraE yb
.flesmih gnisuor ,sivlE saw ti dna seye ym
.mih rof llac fo tros enituor tsom eht saw siht
,yaw fo thgir cilbup eht no ,noitcidsiruj rieht edistuo tops gniksub a nesohc dah I dna sivlE
.deltrats ,deppiy-pley I dna
”.tuoba no gniog erew uoy tahw hctac etiuq t’ndluoc
”…enod si s’nitsiwt-liat taht nehw tuB“
.dnuof d’eh tfelc kcils gnidleiy eht gnirolpxe ylregae
?thgiarts taht teg yeht t’nac yhW
.denilcni os eb uoy n’fi
,sgel sih dniheb dna neewteb ecalp yramotsuc eht ni ,ereht dediser won selcitset egral owT
oot dedne yeht neht
”?ti toG  .nottub eht sserp neht
?uoy ot deneppah tahW“
tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
”.ssoB ,dnammoc ym si hsiw ruoY“ ”.revE
dekoorc tneb saw nif-edis enO
.dnim ym degnahc I fi won tuo mih hsup ot gnitsixe noitpo on htiw ni mih tel ot tliub ydob wen ym
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
…re …ehs …re …eh saW
noinapmoc ruoy fo pleh eht htiw tub …mrof suoiverp ruoy etacilper yltcerid tonnac I“
rae ym desserac sreksihw god gnilffuns-reviuQ
denoitnem reven moM-ateZ  ?yllaeR“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”!won ti xif ot deen eW“ ”…on ,lleW“
,teef ym ot delggurts I
.eno deniats-dratsum eht detpmorp
retrohs gniworg sekorts citnarf sih
.noitomocol detoof-ruof fo gnah eht thguac I sa ydaets gniworg noos tub tsrif ta ylbbow tiag ym
llems-god-tew-surtse sa
.erofeb gnorw os demees dah tahw mohtaf etiuq t’ndluoC
noitasnes eht ta ssilb ni delworg-elbmur
.tis dna tneitap eb esaelP
…mmh …rE  .maeb eht ni thguac tog dna pu nar rehto eht dna reggel-owt eht ta gnimia saw I
,lleW“ ”?uoy deifirgomsnart yeht gniyas uoy erA“  .dekaeuqs yggiZ
!em ot taht ekil gniht a od sivlE tel ot gniog I saw yaw oN
?flesti deriaper gniht eht daH  ?won tahW
.yawa teg ot gniyrt
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
,tuo deppets reciffo elgnis a sa nezorf dehctaw I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
.erom gnihton tub senihw-kcilc ekil-drow fo seires a tuo thguorb dna niaga deirt I
.rennam fo tros yrotailicnoc a ni
.did uoy ffuts rof elbuort ni gnitteg fo derit m’I dna erus rof su no pu wolb annog si sihT  .em yrT“ ”!t’ndluow uoy groZ“ ”!moM-
,noos namuh ot kcab gnignahc eb d’I
.gnisaet tsuj saw I“
!uoy knahT  !ssoB uoy knahT“
neve hguone paehC  .paehc tub
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
niaga reifirgomsnart eht deson I
.droffa ot em rof neve
.aera niorg dna ylleb ym ni gnorts yllaicepse
?oot daeh ym ni thguoht taht tup reifirgomsnart eht daH
?doog nmad os leef elkcit rae elpmis a dluoc woH
.enips ym pu gnireviuq seslup cirtcele teews tnes edam eh bats gnirehtils ynit hcae sa mih tsniaga kcab gnihsup
derumrum dna ruf keehc ym delzzun-ffins eH
…rethgual lausac fo dnuos neddus eht ta gniremmah straeh
dna elgna retteb a rof kcen ym dehcterts I
?wohemos daeh ym pu dessem reifirgomsnart eht saH
.ytpme yltnerruc era sreffub noitarebbigarpus ym llA“ neht reifirgomsnart eht morf ecneliS
”?ti tuoba uoy htiw drow a dah dna edis reh no tsud retsalp eht was ehs yawa thgir dnA
levon retskcirt lacigam siH
noissimrep uoy tnarg ylgnilliw I flaheb sih no os riaffa das siht ni hceeps fo tfig eht tsol yldas sah yelserP .rM  !eruS“ mih dlot dna emit driht a tah pit eht degdun-eot I
.sgut gnilbmuts prahs wef a tsuj htiw tuo ti dekrow eh tub mih rof redrah boj taht edam yawaedih depmarc-thgit ruO
.oot esab sinep sih ni gniht tonk ykaens taht dna
!cisum ruoy evol I
sksid elzzum gnislup-wolg tnecsediriv eerht dna
,ssenregae sselemahs ni gnirepmihw
seye eht ni em dekool eH
,won elbappotsnu ,xamilc deiznerf ot esir mih tlef I
.sevlesruo rof gnikrow reifirgomsnart eht teg ro sneila esoht dnif ot deen ew
?tey gnikrow gniht taht evah uoy oD“
uoy mrofni ot terger I dna
…ebyam ot yaw driew ynnuf a ni
.em deifirgomsnart wen ehT  .em dnA
ratiug ym ot eybdoog
…elgrug dna ssih duol a draeh I
.seiddub elttil esoht gnissim saw yllaer I tub nialpmoc ot tnaw t’ndid I
ti/ehs/eh em esucxe—
,nwod ratiug ym tes dna
.taht rof deen oN“
?sgel gnivom-driew esoht dnA
.ot tnaw uoy fi ,ko s’tahT“
.roivaheb ddo ym deciton dah eh fi ees ot ecnalg dessarrabme na sivlE gnikaens
.regnol tib a ereh teiuq yats dluohs ew tub ,ylbaborP“
kcen sih pin-elzzun ot drawrof denael I
dehgis I ”?edis ruoy yb ’nilwoh god ’nuoh eniuneg a taht si dnA
dna …dna ti ot dnuora teg d’ew ,dnim reven
er’yehT  ?yawyna ,reifirgomsnart a teg neve uoy did erehW
!tnaem I tahw ton s’taht sivlE
.rehtie eltbus ton saw sivlE
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”.sksir yrassecennu ekat ot deen oN
dehgis I  .ti fo retnec eht ni su htiw yznerf gnideef rac dauqs a fo emoc ylbissop dluoc doog oN  .og ot emiT
siht pu tpek eh fi dellik htob su teg ot gniog saw sivlE  ?nug a ti saW
”xoF s’pihS“ cimocbew dna seirots s’rednebraE
,swaperof sih htob htiw ylismulc ecived eht thguac sivlE dna nwod dereknuh I
,yznerf gnittur a ni derepmihw-piy sivlE dna
.mih htaeneb hctib eilloc dezarc-taeh
.ruf ym morf retaw ssecxe fo syarps gnittalps taerg koohs dna
,mih dnuora ecselaoc ot nageb ssenyarg-revlis gninihs ytsiM
.em thguorb taht erusaelp fo hsur neddus eht ta taorht ym ni thgit gnihctac htaerb ,deredduhs
,elam neeb dah elor s’eissaL rof srotca eninac eht lla ylraeN
.gnikool-evisnepxe etiuq erew meht fo emoS
lleW“ ”!namuh si sivlE
dellems eh dna elcsum dedroc revo depard ylesool dna gnilkcirt-pird saw tlep siH
neht dna esuap tnelis gnoL
.ssenlooc gnihserfer eht yojne ot nageb dna ,ti ot demotsucca emaceb I neht tub
?tey deciton uoy t’nevah ssoB“
sivlE“ ,dna ,groZ dessih ”?reifirgomsnart taht teg uoy did erehW  !pots yggiZ“
,rac lortap sih ot detaerter dna ylwols ffo dekcab eh esuaceb mih dekoops evah tsum ti tuoba gnihtemos neht
.yawa kcab ot nageb yletaidemmi dna mrala ni kcab knarhs ohw
!meht fo eno degnahc ylno ti esruoc fO
.sgel god yletinifeD  .sgel goD  .sey…rE
?gniod I ma tahw parc ,hO
.esiwrehto ro namuh ,esoht fo eno dessessop regnol oN
,mih morf yawa deirruh I dna
,demialcorp dna noitangidni suoethgir ni flesmih deffup yggiZ
?naicisum a ot si taht gniyonna woh tsuj fo erawanu yllaer eh saw
,em sdrawot ti gnuws eh dna
.skcubecaps noillim ruof ytfif …fo tnuocsid ecnecselosbo lanoitidda evitalumuc a suniM  .won ti evah I  .dnim reveN
ris ,em esucxE  ?riS“
,gninthgil sa kciuq dewollof eh dna mih morf yawa dekrej I
.nottub gnirif eht desserp  eH
.em ediseb ,esolc yltew flesmih desserp sivlE dna eson ym dellif
.sey ,hA  ?etad eht …re …dnA
,thgit kcuts llits rehtegot doots ew tsal ta tuo detros dna elbatrofmoC
!sgnilhtrae modnar gniyfirgomsnart dnuora og tsuj t’nac uoY
,won ezis emas eht raen erew ew dna
,ees uoy ,alubeN barC eht ni ruot no erew ew…“
,em ta gnirats yledur
”!tiaW“ ”—ot esnes ekam t’nseod
.llac a su yap ot evom eht no ylerus erew seiddub ecilop-ytic rieht dna ydaerla eciwt yb gnilwocs emoc dah sdraug eht tub
?detnaw uoy tahw siht t’nsI  ?gnorw s’tahw ssoB“ denihw dna
,nac god dnuoh a ylno sa enogebeow dekool
.ylsuoiruc ti ffins ot ytinutroppo eht koot I dna
sehcnuah delcsum-nael
,derepsihw eh ”!yggiZ“
tsuj tI  ?ffo uoy pir ot gniyrt syawla ssenisub cisum eht ni ydobyreve si yhW
.yas ot tnaem dah I tahw ton s’taht tub ,dekrab I
”?gnikniht uoy erew kcuf eht tahW
srennam ym fo em gnidnimer ,tsirw ym degdun sivlE litnu ylknalb kcab derats I
,rettam t’nseod ,dnim reveN
derepsihw sivlE dna rae ym ni elffuns-elzzum dimiT
neddus gnidnes pit-eugnot sih
”.erew uoy tcepsus I  .sey …rE“
.em ot raelcnu si dnammoc ruoy noitidda ni dna ,noitacifirgomsnart-fles rof detar ton ma I tub yrros ma I“
?ekas s’ytip rof ,tes eht hsinif em tel tsael ta uoy t’nac ,sedud ,tahc annaw uoy fI
,dehsinotsa ylraelc
,tekcop llarevo mined a ni peed dnah eno tsurht groZ dna
”.sivlE si sihT“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tol gnikrap s’dnalecarG ni srac gnoma tnemlaecnoc thguos eW
.ecalp ruo ni moordaeH xaM no dengis neht
suoegrog eht otni ,drawnwod dna ,drawtuo yllufeelg knups god dnuoh toh niht fo tfig rieht pmup dna tsal ta hcnelc meht tlef
,thguoht lla gnimlehwrevo em dessessop sgnileef esohT
.tsol era stnetnoc reffub lla snoitacificeps yrotcaf ot teser ma I nehW“
”?yltnecer teser neeb I evaH
…kcab mrof namuh ym em evag yeht fi ,taht tpecca dluoc I tub setunim wef tsal eseht fo noitcellocer ym esol ot emahs a eb
tub yb emac srac fo stoL
delzzun dna deffins eH
?sggiZ ,gnikniht uoy erew tahW“
,edis ym no ,ssarg eht no gniyl saw I deraelc sesnes ym nehw dna ,tahw etiuq rebmemer t’nod I
etib sih gnisaeler
…niorg ym tsniaga esolc gnisserp selcitset sih tlef dna tsurht hcae
.ssarg remmus neerg fo
,yltfos derepmihw I dna
,derongi I dna sivlE hcihw
.dluohs yeht yaw eht gnivom toN  .driew
.netsil dna pots yllautca ot tsrif eht erew setakspaehc owt ym dna ,snairtsedep wef
”?taht raeh uoy diD  !sivlE“
…dna ytinamuh ym dna eciov ym dna ratiug ym tsoL
.oot rekcep yM  .haey ho
”?emit siht melborp eht s’tahW
”!oga setunim wef a tsuj em degnahc uoY
.esrow neve era seno ythguan eht dna
esolc deimmihs sivlE .ti ekil
,syawedis dehsarht I dna em ta reifirgomsnart eht demia yggiZ
,stiucsib god owt su dessot dna tekcop sih ni dehcaer reciffo ehT
,god.ecioveht ta
?elacs yggans a hcus uoy era yhW  !groZ ,no emoC“
?ledom dnasuohT ruoF kraM niarborciM a taht si dnA
delbmurg-thguoht I
.tuo dekrow gnieb era sliated ronim eseht elihw esu etaidemmi ruoy rof flesym etacolla nac I edoc noitacifitnedi citcalag ruoy em evig ll’uoy fI
.ereht ruf neddos eht gnimoorg-elbbin dna gnikcil
”!sekam yad a ecnereffid a tahW
.eissaL kcikedis sih saw I dna ,saw eh ,sey
!efil lautriv sih evas ot ecnad t’nac edud tahT  .wonk uoy ,tsom eht truh tahw s’tahT
,noitilov tuohtiw gnizeeuqs-rettulf
mih tsniaga kcab ylsuousnes flesym dehsup I emit a retfA
”0.2 etoyoC weN“
,em dna kcoR fo gniK tnanever eht
.lacitnedi etiuq ton ,on—
.thgir ton s’gnihtemos …em esucxE“
kcab rehtruf detacol erew spil avluv ym tub
dias dna ylevitaicerppa ria eht deffins dna elims yggod-dnuoh lufepoh ediw a delims eH  ”.kniht I  !era uoy won dna em htiw etam dluoc uoy os taeh ni erew uoy dehsiw uoy dias uoY
”.nottub eht sserp neht
.eno ekil dekool eruS  ?elzzum god a—
seot ym no llat doots neht
!yzarc s’tahT  !sivlE  ?tahW“
.lla ta denrecnoc yldrah demees sivlE
.erofeb neeb dah eh naht resolc pu gnidne
!reifirgomsnart emoh esu lanosrep dnasuohT ruoF kraM ledom
,deregnif ruof saw tI
deppay dna em ot kcab denrut neht
”!gnihtyna gniod t’nsaw I  .egroeG …re
”—ot gniyrt tsuj saw I
,ti revo deregnil I
.esaelp ,epyh eht tuC“
?sthgir ot lla tup ot noos kcab gnimoc eb sneila eht dluoW
,gnilims ,em rof llits flesmih dleh sivlE
dnih ym morf yawa deyats sivlE sa gnol sa dna
.daeh ym ni sdrow eht emac ”,etelpmoc noitacifirgomsnarT“ dna
”?em rof dnammoc deifidom ro wen a evah uoy oD
,evom ot moor fo tuo nar tub niaga dekrej I
…rood kcab ym hgin dnuor ’neffinS oooor-wa …god ’nuoh a tub ’nihtun t’nia uoY“  2
…tsuj lufniap toN
…tah snoitanod ym dna
.driew saw tahT  .woW“
.hguone noos thgir taht tup ll’ew tub
.meht erongi ot dedneterp I tub won noitnetta rof gnilgna erew srehctaw-eldwad etakspaehc ruO
”?owt ytrof …hU  .parc ,wA“
.od ot tahw wenk ydaerla ydob
!yaw taht ta dekool eb ot egnarts oS
.moc.nozamA no esahcrup rof elbaliava si
no dehsup ,og dluoc ti sa peed sa
!llwowl-wwwoH dna eit sih tset ot kcab dellup sivlE
.og uoy erehw rettam on emas eht lla s’tI
,no meht esu ot taeh ni hctib a deen uoy tub stun ruoy peek ot emoclew er’uoY
,lortnoc ym dnoyeb em nihtiw gnidils mih leef ot egnarts-lufssilb oS
.swal lacol yb detibihorp erehw diov si tcartnoc selas sihT
.kcikedis eninac gnimrahc-dworc detsoob-niarb sih
…uoy htiw eb lliw gnieb-selas niarborciM A
,sselnoitom ezorf eW
.esac yna ni noos gnikcap su gnidnes eb dluow sdraug ytiruces dnalecarG ehT
.od dluow god elamef knurd-taeh a ekil edisa liat sih gnippilf dna
,ti delkcit-ssik ylyhs dna niaga rae ym delffuns sivlE  ”.kO“
.ecin …yllaer
,dehgis dna deggurhs I
.ereht neddih ecived  emos rof gnihcraes ylraelc
sdraug eht morf seciov-pissog eldI
.mih tsniaga drah pu flesym gnipmuh dna esolc mih gnillup
!sivlE“ mih ot thguoht I yllufyalP
.dedeen I noitaripsni tihsllub eht em gnivig dna
enips ym pu gnigrus sehsalf-elgnit suoiciled
.htap sti ni gnihtyreve gnihcnerd dna syawedis ylwols gnivom
?em ot gniod sivlE si tahW
dluow tI  ?ynam woh tub seiromem ym gnipiw eb d’yeht dias dah sneila ehT
,liat a dnA  .enim yletinifed
.ecnalab detoof-ruof fo tros etauqeda na gniveihca yllautneve
,htiwhtrof secnatsmucric yrros ruo yfitcer ot
”?segelivirp gnirahs cihtapme-otingoc s’noinapmoc ruoy fo edargpu na gnitseuqer uoy erA
,won daeh ym raen saw knalf sih os denrut dah sivlE
.nwo ym sa psag-erutpar sih derahs knil ruo hguorht dna
”.dnim on yap eno on ’na emit ed lla klof su tiw ’nissem eb sneilA
fles gnippird yggahs nwo ym htiw fi gnidleihs ,ti revo deldduh I os ecnahc a ekat ot tnaw t’ndid I tub ,ylbaborP
mih ezirohtua esaelp ti ta er’uoy elihw dnA  !seY“
!enoyna ot taht llet reve uoy t’nod sivlE  !oN“
”…yppup a saw I nehw
”!thgit os uoY  …edisnI
.yllautca ,tol a etiuQ
,ti htiw ffo klaw ot nageb dna niaga reifirgomsnart eht pu koot I os gnitsaw saw emiT
…tuo semoc dna gib sworg neht llams ni sedils god elaM
?gnihtyreve desare dna eltbus ssel saw epiw yromem rieht fi tahw tub
,em nihtiw tonk kciht taht dnuora smsaps sselpleh ni dehcnelc ydob dna gnireviuq dehcra kcab yM
”?praY“ ”?deneppah tahW
!retlehs lamina taht morf em koot uoy ecnis em rof enod ev’uoy gniht tsecin eht si sihT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,rednebraE yb
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.eslup gnidne-reven teews wols yb
.niarb ym otni deriw-drah gniruop dna
.daeh ym gnillif sdrow-thguoht gnirettan eht tuo enut ot tseb ym gniyrt
!erofeb god tew a no llor ot egru eht tlef reven dah I  .no llor rO
!yawa og t’nod esaelP  !oN“ ”—retteb a dnif nac I erus m’I
,yawa gninrut ylhsipeehs ,dias eh ”,ssoB yrroS“
,syar ammag lahtel htiw
!tihsllub ohcam evitcetorprevo
!hhgrrA“ ”!yawyna ,thgir llems uoY“
.em ta demia saw ti os leehw retspmud a htaeneb reifirgomsnart eht degdew dna ylleb ym no enorp nwod yal I  ”!tuo uoy tset s’tel eeg-yllog …lleW
.htaehs sih morf tuo gnikeep pit kcoc tew der detniop eht dna
,dezingocer ton edoC“
,won dnuos gnimmuh tnanoser tfos a gnittime saw gniht ehT
!on ssoB“ depley dna
dedaf ecnaidar ehT !selppin ynam oS
.eissaL …ekil eilloc A
,hcuot gniborp a tlef I
.hguone ylisae namuh uoy ekam nac I
”.dnammoc sih ta meht tnemelpmi lliw I
…dna oot esoht fo eno dah ,sey
,liat ot daeh morf em hguorht egrus snoitasnes gnilgnit
dna meht fo eno degnahc ylno tI  !kooL
.thgir gnileef ton
,rethgit mih deppirg neht
”.ssoB yrroS  .ssoB ,seY“
.thgir gnikrow etiuq t’nsaw llits trap taht tub ,oot deirt ro
!uoy ekil sgod tuoba sgnos era erehT
…fo tnecs eht htiw hcir dna gnipag ylthgils tils edisni eht
.lla retfa ,mraw ylbatrofmocnu neeb dah yad ehT
pirts yawkrap edisdaor nwom-wen eht no ylluferac ti gnitser
;tsurht hcae htiw regral werg eh sa ssenlluf ot em gnihcterts
thgit mih dezeeuqs dna delworg I
.gninoitcnuflam yliraropmet eb ot raeppa snoitcennoc tsoh ym tub em esucxe
ezis lluf ot dednetsid esab sinep sih ni tonk eht sa
,kcatta sih denodnaba sivlE dna cinap ni delwoh I
,oot kcab dehsup sivlE
.sgel ym neewteb strap etavirp elyts-god-elamef ,si taht …elyts-eissaL
.hguone doog saw ti fi gnirednow ereht detnap I ,rehtar rO
,teef ruof ot esor dna ecnalab sih thguac ylkciuq ,eciwt delbbarcs-gel eH
!tnellecxE  !tnellecxE“
”,nairutcrA ,haey ,haeY“ …dna
dna dop a ni saep sa ekila
?ereht kcab tuoba eson mih tel did I fi tahw
”.tbed ruoy ni reverof sevlesruo redisnoc llahs eW
.yltnetni ti gnivresbo ,reifirgomsnart degamad eht revo wol dehcuorc saw yggiZ
.sretspmud gnilcycer fo retsulc a dniheb ecaps dedahs worran eht ni
?thgirla uoy era yggiZ“
”.niaga ti htiw ssem ew erofeb elcyc riaper dna citsongaid-fles sti etelpmoc ot sdeen gniht sihT
.era uoy esruoc fO
em desuffus ecnaidar neerg ylhtraenU
,gniht dam a ekil gniremmah dna thgit gnihctulc ,won em ni yaw eht lla saw eH  .retsaf
.tuoba yrrow ot gnihton dah I dne
,emit siht ssensuoicsnoc esol t’ndid I tub
,regnol tib a no deirrac
.enips ym nwod selgnit-erusaelp gnihsinotsa
.sivlE ot revo ti deson dna reifirgomsnart eht degdew-nu I ”.detpecca sredrO“
.looc ot nugeb dah dna
esahcrup rof gniredisnoc eb ot tnemegduj doog lanoitpecxe ssessop uoy ylraelC
.rae gnipoord tfos nwo sih elzzun
,seizood emos nees ev’I dna ,sebur drieW
kcohs ni dexifsnart derats I
”.dessucsid tsuj ew sa segnahc noitacifirgomsnart ekam ot
aivirt doowylloH sselesu fo lesrom a sa rethgual-piy yggod sseleciov
tneitap eb ll’uoy fI
dna no thguac tca ruO
;sseldrager yrots ym htiw no deirrac I tub ,hctac ton did eh tfird ym dna niaga tah pit eht degdun-eot I
?mrah eht saw tahw lla retfa dna
”…yldab oot sreffub noitarebbigarpus eht etanimatnoc t’ndid taht epoh
.os ti gniyojne s’eh dna ,rae na tsuj s’ti tub taht od mih gnittel eb t’ndluohS
.noitisop taht rof elbaliava yltnerruc ton ma I
peed toh tlef tsuj
”.wonk uoy diputs ton m’I  .erus ,haey ,haeY“
…groZ taht potS  !wo—
”…raer ym ta eb noos ll’uoy rae ym leef uoy fi soC
.tnelis werg daeh ym ni esion-retnab gnihsinotsa taht dna gniht eht deppord I ”—era serutaef lanoitpecxe ynam ym gnomA
.emit on ni thgir ti evah lliw yggiZ bis-evih ym tub noitcnuflam lacinhcet a fo tib a gnivah er’ew“
,em ’lot enod ammom yM“ denoorc dna
.yawyna ,dlot erew ew tahw ton s’tahT“
,mih morf nwod depmuj dna noitartsurf ni delworg I
”.oot detalubmurmocsid sti kniht I“
!namuh eb ot desoppus m’I …I“ dias I
syawedis redrah deknik liat ym noitilov tuohtiW
,ti ta nwod derats eH
tsrif ta yllufyalp mih depmub I sa
liat a fo bulc kciht gnol sih gniggaw dna rehto eht ot dne eno morf ylregae em gniffins saw eH
”!yrots sih llet nam eht teL  !yggiZ“
.gniht siht etavitca ot nottub eht desserp I woh was uoY“ dias I
,hguone erus dna dnuor deldis eH
.yb esolc pots a ot gniwols rac ecilop a ees ot pu dekool I dna
.hguone doog saw ecalp gnidih eht fi gnirednow
”.sey em llet esaelP
.flesmih etagitsevni ot nwod deppolf ylneddus neht
”goD ’nuoH a tub ’nihtuN“
,llew sa yggiZ ssapmocne ot gnidaerps ylkciuq
.noitartnecnoc ni tuhs seye nwo sih dehcnip neht
,su dniheb llaw etercnoc eht morf nwod dedacsac-ecnuob dna daehrevo decra yarps elzzon-retaw ecrof-lluf neht
”?tey enog er’yeht knihT“
,reifirgomsnart eht morf yawa devom dna teef ym ot esor I
.revo ti od tsuj ll’ew
!neve ,sivlE ekil god emoS
.ydaer dna doog s’eh nehW  .retal
.yrrufoS dna ytiniffaruF no elbaliava era
defray dna kcab knarhs I ”?kcuf annaW
thguac tnemevoM  .tnaveler ti deredisnoc ton dah spahrep ro ,tcaf llams taht gnissim erew selif atad s’reifirgomsnart eht demees ti tub ,tcaf fo tniop ni
”,hgih liat rey elkcit nA“
”?em ecudes ot gniyrt uoy erA
?he ,s’nilhtrae tib-owt efilwol ’o elpuoc a tsej s’ew ,nom yeH“
”?yaw siht emac yeht knihT“
!noonretfa eht ni etal os rof ereht srac fo tol a erew eruS
.tnaw uoy noitnetta eht lla teg ll’uoy dna ,sedarmoc ,nwod yenom elttil a tuP
.ffo raf ton ,gniugra yltsenrae erew yggiZ dna groZ  .em ediseb ssarg eht no sselnoitom yal sivlE dna
”.yralubatsnoC thgirypoC nayerfillaG  eht ot sdeed live rieht gnitroper rof tnemhsinup sa
noitnetta ym thguac tnemevap no serit rac fo elbmur gnidnirg teiuq eht detatiseh I sA
.thgit su dekcol dna
.ekorts hcae htiw mih hguorht gniraes noisnet teews gniworg eht
!pmur YM naem t’ndid I pmuh ot pmur a uoy desimorp I nehW
…’segnahc latnem‘ tuoba gnihtemos noitnem did tI
.spil dna hteet dna eson revo ylsseltser gnikcilf pit eugnot ym
.gniyalp ym deppots dah ohw eno eht s’tahT