.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.nwo sih fo seirots emos etirw ot emit sekam eh ,skoob daeR-oT fo draoh sih morf gnidaer ton s’eh nehW
,noitinifed yb ,si tuo gnimoC
.teop eht yb daer
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
mrywkooB irikeneN yb meop a
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,gnisselb dexim a eb nac ytilibisiv taht tahT
,”oT oG ot tihsnekcihC ooT saW I
.egap yrruFoS sih no dnuof eb nac smeop sih fo eroM
doom eht niur dna sreeuq eht lla ta kool dnA
yltnecer desolc uoy draeh I
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
tuoba s'ti tahw ees dna og ll'I yademoS
flesym dlot syawla tub ,neeb reven d'I
.teop eht yb daeR  .ytissecen a
”oT oG ot tihsnekcihC ooT saW I raB yaG eht ot edO“ saw sihT
htaed fo tnemecnuonorp sA
sselehtenon ti sekam
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
nwot llams ym morf koot eugalp eht gniht erom enO
.ti gniod ot tniop on eb dluow ereht esiwrehto
.moc.irikenen.www no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,ytilibisiv fo tca na
ta dekwag gnieb ssim oT
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
esuac sa nevig saw cimednaP
,neht gnileef railucep a tahW
og dluow sklof thgiarts taht draeh dah I
.seirots setirw dna semag sekam ohw
raB yaG eht ot edO“   yojne esaelP