,reh edisnI   .ytinrete
erutcurts ralucric a gnimrof
,niaga llef thgin nehW
.retaw eht otno maeb reh tsac ehs
.eromyna toN .yllaer ton tuB
.senob nedoow derehtaew reh ni peed nwod ti tlef ehS
hctaw ot rehtegot ereht deyats yeht dnA
,yks eht derevoc cirbaf yarg sihT .enola dna
.esuohthgil eht rof ssenkrad fo lluf regnol on saw dlrow ehT
.lla fo tsom reh dedeen dlrow eht taht
,kwah rehtona deppalf naeco eht revO
snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
,yademos ebyam taht thguoht
,slevart sih lla ni tuB
,dnuorg eht evoba elim-flah a morF
.eulb peed eht ni ereht tuo
,niaga flesreh ni deveileb ehS
egdiR aicacA dnoyeB
,rood derracs ,nepo eht hguorht welf eH
thgil fo maeb a tsac esuohthgil eht
.erofeb dah efil yreve sa ,reh morf yawa ylf dna
,niaga reh edisni devil enoemos taht desaelp os ,ynapmoc yrehtaef reh htiw dethgileD
.dlo saw esuohthgil ehT
”esuohthgiL a dna kwaH a fO“
.thgin hcae naeco eht revo tuo thgil reh gnidnes
.sffilc yggarc eht no nerrab doots esuohthgil ehT
,tnemom taht nI   .kcab derats eH
,eniatnoF eralC ymA yb
.siht wonk ot dneirf derehtaef reh ees ot deen t’ndid esuohthgil ehT
ettelevon aneyh cihpromoporhtna eht dna
,gnilkraps eht revo detrovac elamef eht dna eh sa
.aes ot tuo dekool kwah eht
.efil sih lla dlrow eht evoba deraos dah kwah deliat-der ehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,edistuo was eh dlrow naeco kcalb-yarg-eulb eht ni
dehctaw esuohthgil ehT
,denekrad seiks reh woh rettam on ,tlef ehs ytpme woh rettam on
.gnitiaw ,gnirevihs
.krab dna sgiwt fo slufnolat gniyrrac
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,rood derracs ,nepo eht hguorht welf skwah deliat-der eht ,yad txen ehT
,srats eht ekilnU
,ni dellor tsim gninrom ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.epoh lla tsol dah ehs
,esacriats nedoow dega eht revo
.dlrow eht dedlofne tsim s’thgin eht dna nwod tnew nus eht sa
.doom reh fo evitcelfer ssenkrad erutamerp ni doots esuohthgil eht litnu ti gniwollawS
.secaf laudividni fo snoillim rieht dezingocer eh
dehctaw dna ereht dehcrep eH
ssenkrad eht otni thgil reh tnes ehS
.syad lareves rof ylippah devil
.ti ees dluow enoyna erus t’nsaw ehS
,eniatnoF eralC ymA yb ”esuohthgiL a dna kwaH a fO“ saw sihT
”esuohthgiL a dna kwaH a fO“:yojne esaelP
.krab eht htiw denil yeht hcihw
.yppah saw esuohthgil eht dnA
,emac ecno thgil ecnehw morf mroftalp eht fo esab eht morF
tliub neeb dah ehS
:sffilc yggarc reh no
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.swodniw esuohthgil deniats eht tuo esirnus dna tesnus eht
#   .yoj rof tuohs srats eht edam dna
.sthgin ymrots eht hguorht ynapmoc reh peek ot
.enola dna ytpme doots esuohthgil ehT
despmilg kwah eht
.noitcif yrruf fo rohtua cifilorp a dna tsigoloib efildliw a si ohw
.snoitacilbuP laoG yb
.mih nwonk dah ehs esuaceb rethgirb tlef ehs
sseltser worg dluow skwah eht
.rehtegot dnal sdrawot kcab welf neht dna
,trap sih rof ,kwah eht dnA
.gniraos erew sdrib
.gnihtyreve revo yretaw yal ecnaillirb egnaro-wolley a dna
.kwah eht ta wodniw a hguorht derats ehS
,tesnus eht dewollaws tey ton dah gof ehT
.esuohthgil eht deretne eno oN
.def ylregae kwah eht hcihw no
.moc.eniatnoferalcyma.www no
.esor nus eht ,gninrom txen ehT   #   .deyarp dna
kwah deliat-der eht
moor nretnal eht ot pu dna ,esacriats nedoow dega eht revo
,esuohthgil tnednopsed taht fo ssenkrad eht ni dnA
.rednaw ot deen on tlef
,tesnus dna esirnus yreve erahs ot ylimaf a dah ehs
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
tsim eht decreip ecnaillirb reH
.ees elpoep naht erom hcum os was eH
,mroftalp eht no tas kwah eht sa ,tesnus eno tuB
si yrots s’yadot dna
.esuohthgil eht fo tuo welf elam ehT   .wenk eh
.revol suolaej a ekil esirnus eht gnipolevne
,edirb wen a ekil delkraps ehS
,derracs dna deppihc saw rood nedoow ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.reh deripsni egdelwonk taht dna ,esoprup reh gnillifluf saw ehs tuB
.sgniht gnivil fo syaw gnirednaw eht wenk ehS
,tesnus dna esirnus yreve rof moor nretnal eht ot pu welf eh tuB
,dlrow eht ni erehwemoS
esuohthgil eht dna kwah ehT   #   .retaw eht otno
.swodniw deniats sti htiw
,ylluferac sgiwt eht decalp yeht
.pu worg dluow skcihc eht
.sgniw sih pu gnidlof dna skcihc emos gnisiar ,tsen a gnidliub ,etam a gnitruoc
.yks wolley eht tsniaga der gniwolg liat reh fo srehtaef eht
.ssendas dna emit
,sevaw dna sdniw yb yawa deleep neeb dah esuohthgil eht no tniap fo sepirts etihw dna der lufyoj-ecno ehT
doots esuohthgil ehT
.tsrif ta t’ndid eh ,tsael tA
.yks rieht dekohc taht tsim eht etipsed ehtaerb ot delggurts srats gnipsag eht dna ,llef thgiN
:nwod gnilttes morf mih tpek tahw erus t’nsaw eH
devol saw ehs taht citatsce
,pmal esuohthgil ytsud eht woleb noisserped eht nI
,aes eht ssorca erif laidromirp emos morf ekoms fo sregnif ekil
.sretaw sseltser dna krad eht nopu wolg reh tsac reven esuohthgil eht tuB
.emac niaR .llef thgiN
,star dna ecim fo ylppus ydaets a niatsus ot seciverc ynam reh ni noitategev hguone saw erehT
.rehtegot dlo worg dlrow eht dehctaw esuohthgil eht dna eh dna
.erehw-swonk-ohw drawot stnerruc ria gnola degnulp eh sa
,rehto hcae dnuora gnilriwt
.woleb raf niatnuom a no
#   .gnimoc saw eno on wenk ehS
ssenitpme fo nrevac siht ni
;seitic rieht ni gnivol dna gnithgif dna gniromalc elpoep was eH
.esuohthgil eht was kwah eht
,detsixe llits evoL
maercs gnilwem ,dliw sih sa sseltser sa saw traeh sih—
,emitnaem eht ni tuB
ytpme doots esuohthgil eht erehw ot skcor eht pu gnipeerc
tsekrad demees seiks eht nehw ylesicerp saw tI
wenk esuohthgil eht ,dehctah elamef eht yb dial sgge eht nehW
.wenk eh ,tnemom taht nI
.nruter syawla dluow thgilnus
,moor nretnal eht ot pu dna
.ssarg gnol eht ni htrib gnivig esuom a was eh
eniatnoF eralC ymA yb
.hcaeb a gnikoolrevo sffilc yggarc eht no esuohthgil eht dnuof eh ,yllautnevE
:hturt lufrednow eht dezilaer ehs ,moor nretnal reh dehtab thgil s’nwad sA
.emoh a dnuof reven dah
sgnitirw reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.srehto ot thgil gnirb ot
.thgirla eb dluow gnihtyreve
.emoh enoemos dael dluow ehs
,ega dlo derit reh ni neve
,yllautneve taht wenk ehS
.yrt ot eunitnoc dluow ehs oS
,esuohthgil eht tfel dah kwah eht hguohT
.sgnippord llug htiw deniats moor nretnal eht fo swodniw eht
,ecnaillirb taht nI
tsiM ysatnaf tluda gnuoy eht edulcni skoob reH
.nwonk dah ehs evol eht gnitcelfer ,thgil htiw htrof tsrub ehS
drawno reve mih delleporp gnihtemos tuB
.yrc gnikeirhs a draeh eh
knurt eert a nwod nar ti sa lerriuqs a fo kcab eht no sriah eht no saelf eht was eH
,aes wolley-dna-egnaro