.eye na ot pu ti sdloh dna kcas eht morf skcor neerg eht fo eno pu skcip eH
.etubirtnoc dluoc I dalg tsuj m’I
,nioj sdnaH  .hsalf sthgil
.evisserpmi yrev saw taht erus m’I tub ,yddub ,won thgir ysub adnik m’I“
.ebor sih ta nwod skool eH
.ezeens em ekam ot smees syawla ti tub
,dnuora skool ti sa kcen s’flow lacinahcem eht no slenap rehtael eht sekorts yltneg eH ”.uoy ,ereh emoC“
thgit raeb eht sdloh xof ehT
.dias ufihs ruoy tahw rebmemeR
.nrevac eht ni sgnir eciov tfos s’nrohT
.oog krad eht yb delios yletaidemmi si edalb evitcelfer ylthgirb eht
,rehtegot ehtaerb raeb eht dna xof eht sa sllaf ecneliS
,ecaf s’yddub sih no tnemtnioppasid eht sees nrohT
,syas dna etinavlys fo knuhc eht ta nwod skool eH
.htrof dna kcab gaw ot snigeb liat stI
,ylf sevinK  .sgnilf kcum
,nihtiw morf swolg enots ehT
taht t’ndluow ,tiaw tuB“
mhtyhr s’enotstraeh eht sleef eh ,desolc seyE
.retaw eht ni duolc kcalb a sa revirnwod yawa tfird dna evlossid egduls eht sehctaw dna yldetaeper retaw eht ni ebor sih spid xof ehT
.noinapmoc gnilevart sih dna mih netaerht yeht sa shtiarw evif eht gnikcart ,noitcerid tnereffid a ni gnitniop hcae
”.elbasunu era meht fo flah yllausU
.gnitnahcne rof tnelat a etiuq evah ot mees uoY
,sretsnom tuo gniraelc peek ot evah t’nod eW
.yddub uoy raeh I“ ,syas xof ehT
.worbeye na sesiar eh sa ffats sih pu skcip rykeS
,sedolpxe erutaerc eht sa snoitcerid lla ni seilf egduls kcalB
.sllaw enots krad s’evac eht pu gnithgil yliratnemom
.regna fo hsalf eht
.ecnuob elbeef a sekam yllanif liat s’flow lacinahcem ehT
,etalucitra t’nac raeb ehT
.sdnuow eht sehcuot nrohT nehw hcnilf neve t’nseod
,dlog fo spool htiw edam ssenrah llams a ekil skool tahw pu skcip esnohplA
.nrevac eht sekahs raor gnilgrug peed A
,ylhsipeehs syas nrohT
.eson sih ot regnif eno sesserp dna ,syas eh
.regdab eht dniheb dnats ot spets trohs wef a sekat raeb ehT
.neerg tnaillirb a gniwolg si gnihcuot s’eh etinavlys ehT
.srae rieht no ruf eht gnilffur
.gnitser ,erif eht fo tnorf ni syal won god lacinahcem ehT
,lleps ecnanimuL eht tuo sehtaerb eH
”?yawyna ,rof skcor esoht deen regdab eht did tahW
.emit revo gnitnahcne suounitnoc hguorht ecnenamrep taht etaerc ylwols d’uoy yllareneG
.latsyrc der eht ta kool esolc a sekat dna
,ygrene lacigam tnarre erom yna rof pu noitnetta sih speek ,kcab spets eH
.wol gniyats ,drawrof pets kciuq a sekat dna swalc dehcnerd-egduls ,gnol ylgnilttesnu morf hsals gnimocni na skcud raeb ehT
,ydob yvaeh sih fo erawa
.llaw evac eht no htiarwegduls tsal eht gnicaf ydaerla s’ohw ,raeb eht no tsol si tnemetats ehT
.deird ruf ,raelc sraeT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,retaw gnilppir eht otni nwod skool tsuj rykeS
,sezis lla fo sreniatnoc ssalg ,sebut ,sraeg
.latsedep ssarb elttil a otno enots enillatsyrc der thgirb dezis-tsif a gnicalp
.ecneuqes enur a etacidni ot pu sehcaer eH
.krims a htiw syas eh
,ekirts dnoces a rof ydaer swalc yzoo krad s’htiarw ehT
.esuap emos rykeS sevig enots kcen ehT
,der llud railimaf eht ot sedisbus enots eht morf wolg thgirb ehT
.mih etaicerppa ylurt lliw eno on dna
.ti ot ytilauq gnosgnis ,cimhtyhr a htiw egaugnal tneicna na
.yletaidemmi pu enil smhtyhr ehT
,gnihctiwt strats ydob flow ehT
.eno hcae hguorht hsup ygrene-ihc elttil a gnilennahc deirt I os ,sdleif ecneulfni rof erew yeht dias uoY“ ,sreffo raeb ehT  ”.sretsnom
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,troffe eht htiw mid seye eulb eht sa
.dniheb morf tsehc s’erutaerc eht secreip drows trohs a neht tub
,walc a htiw setacidni regdab eht
htiarw ,esir selkcaH
.mih fo tnorf ni ymene gnippird-rohci eht ekirts ot ffats sih sesiar raeb ehT
,latsyrc eht edisni dnuora ecnuob ot nigeb thgil fo smaeB
dne eht ni tub
,ecalperif eht yb tis regdab dna ,raeb ,xof eht ,retal emit emoS
”,tuo em peerc yllaer sruoy fo seye lacigam esoht wonk uoY“
.tnemezama elbaplap htiw ,syas raeb eht
,esnet dna teiuq neeb dah ylsuoiverp tsuj ohw
ot gniog uoy era tahW ?lleW“
,ni ti stup eh sa dna
,laremehpe erutan sti yb si enotstraeh eht otni derohcna I lleps gninommuS eht ,ees uoY
.si htiarwegduls yddad eht erehw dnim sih ni tbuod on gnivael
latsyrc eht fo tuo stsiwt thgil ehT
.ti otni desufni esnohplA taht tnahc cimhtyhr eht
.nrohT ,yrgna eb ot tnaw t’nod I …I
.muroced fo kcal s’yddub sih rof tnemssarrabme htiw toh gniworg skeehc sih ,raeb eht sksa
ev'yeht ,rebmemer nac eh sa gnol sa smees tI
?yako ,taerg did uoY“
!ahA“ ,smialcxe dna spalc esnohplA
...“  .rekcins a sserppus ot won stpmetta
,mraw ydob sih dna ,lluf ylleb sih htiw ereh ,doog sleef tI
.maets gnipacse dna edisni sraeg gnitacorpicer ylwols eht rof tpecxe tnemevom on ,esnopser on s’ereht ,tsrif tA
.rohtuA eht yb daer ,seirraH nomoloS yb
…fo kool a ,ediw nepo seye siH
.enots tsewen eht gnidirrevo dna deifilpma hcae fo rewop eht
.tluciffid erom elttil a steg emit hcae dna
,tsehc sti no lenap a pu sllup regdab ehT
- hguoht ,ksa ot detnaw I
,kcab skool tsuj regdab ehT
.tuo ekohc ot seganam eh ”,uoy knahT“
,edaf sraeF .sraos epoh
,gninepo eht fo edisni eht rof hcaer ot mees enots eht no sebut ehT
”!HGRAAAAA -ruoy ni oog gnivah ekil uoy teb I ,yeH“ ,syas rykeS
,ecnad owT .luam swalc
,teem seyE sllaf htiarw
,levart ’syad wef a retfA  ~ .tser
.snokceb regdab ehT
”,ereh kcab ruoy no rebmun a did yllaer rekcufkcum taht ,sekiY“  .retaw eht ni tfird dna lriws taht yarg fo sduolc erom gnisaeler
”.gnihtemos ta kool a evah ot uoy tnaw I ,ereH
.regdab eht ot raeb eht morf skool nrohT
.stnemtnahcne dna senur tuoba yldetamina klat rykeS dna regdab ehT .rennid rof yvarg dna stiucsib deraperp ylsuoiciled s’esnohplA gnitae
…ees I“ ,syas raeb ehT
.sekaw flow ,wolg senotS
,osrot eht fo retnec eht ni ytivac a gnilaever
.ti revo siri ssarb a sesolc taht revel a sllup esnohplA dna
.rehtegot llew yalp ot evah yeht dna
.rykeS ,pleh ruoy rof sknahT“
.ecarbme ,yad hcaE
.ytilauq hgih yllaer lla era esehT“
seirots sih fo erom dnif yllautneve thgim uoy dna
.seceip nekorb eht secalper dna ,wap s’esnohplA morf enots wen eht stpecca raeb ehT   .uoy evol I
,edisni ,nwod diaL
,gnitaolf sebut dna sraeg sti htiw enotstraeh eht stfeh eH
.drawkcab thgiarts retsnom eht ecnuob ot ylleb enisru elbazis sih gnisu
,hcnebkrow sih fo retnec eht ni aera na sraelc eH
.rykeS tuoba tnereffid s’gnihtemos dnA
.stniuqs regdab eht ,selggog sih revo snel elprup a gnirewoL
.raeb eht ot tuo enots etinavlys wen a gnidloh ydaerla s’ohw
.osrot eht ni stnev tsuahxe eht fo tuo yltneg pop maets fo sffuP
”.detrats teg s’tel ,thgirlA“  ”.elbuort artxe eht htrow s’ti kniht I
~  ”!hcum os uoy knahT“
.erofeb seno eht htiw mhtyhr s’enots wen eht pu enil ot gnivah emit hcae
”?gninetsil uoy t’nerew ,htgnel ta ti denialpxe eH“
,egattoc eht fo dne eno ta snrub ecalperif A
.stnemragrednu fo ytilitu eht ni eveileb ton seod ylraelc eH
.egduls eht gnivomer fo ssecorp wols eht snigeb osla dna nwod stauqs raeb ehT
,ni kcab ti spool dna ygrene gnidecer eht fo emos serutpac ti
,ssenthgirb esnetni na htiw swolg enots kcen ehT
”?ti si ,suoregnad…ton s’tI“
,enozo fo tnih a yb deinapmocca
.dnim sih ni duol tbuod-fles eht ,enots eht sekat rykeS
.tuo sllac rykeS ”?eeS“
.kcen eht ni eno dna ,seenk dna swoble eht ni hcae eno
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,der-egnaro peed a snrut tesnus eht sA
.sbmil sti esu ot woh fo tnarongi tey pup nrobwen a ekil
- tcesretni senil enur eht erehw tops a no
- erom yna ti erutpac yllaer t’nseod ’dneirf‘ drow eht - sih nioj ot
”,senots etinavlys eht fo neves deen I ,rykeS ,yakO .dooG“
.edam snalp ,traeh yraeW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ria eht morf raeg ssarb a skcip eh sa enotstraeh eht fo eroc gniwolg eht fo ygrene eht esufni
.senur eht daer ot seunitnoc eh sa rykeS sllif rednoW  ”.yako
,mih dniheb yltcerid mlap sih stniop eh dna ffats eht ffo seilf neht wap tfel siH
,ereh thgir gnitratS
”?nwod uoy tog s’tahW .yddub yeH“
ygrene nwo sti sah enots hcae ,ytilauq doog lla er’yeht hguoht neve taht swonk eH
.spots emit ,sees dniM
,telracs repeed htiw dexim seuh knip fo slriws
.epahs cificeps yrev a otni dneb wap hcae fo sregniF
…otni swolf ti ekil skool ,gnidnib ranalp-snart a s’eno siht ,ho
,sdnopser esnohplA
.sretsnom erom oN“
,pu skcip ezeerb mraw A
”.ecitnerppa na no ekat ot stnaw retnahcne eht fi ees nac ew ebyam ,yeH
.ygrene der tnarre eht teem ot esir sdnah sih dna flesmih sdnuorg eh sa sdraobroolf eht otni ylthgils gid dna nethgit swalc toof siH
.tuo rekcilf dna yliratnemom wolg senots ehT
- ”?yug siht dnif uoy did erehW“
”?siht fo lla htiw pu emoc ot uoy rof ekat ti did gnol woH
~   ”.mih ekat nac ew kniht I“
,nihc sih sehctarcs dna yawa skool esnohplA
.sbmil dewalc ,gnol yliree sti slruc dna maercs lufniap ,gnilgrug a tuo stel hcihw
si nrohT ereh dnA
.htaerb a tuo stel raeb ehT
.xetrov ygrene na gnizilibats tuoba gnihtemos
.tfel eht ot ffo strap fo elip a dna ecafrus sti no sebut dna sraeg fo snib suoirav
.efil sih rof gnithgif kcuts eb syawla ll’eh taht
,daehrevo htrof dna kcab tilf swollaws evaC
.tuo erugif ot emit gnol yrev a em koot ecneuqes tahT
.sekauq htrae ,taeb straeH
.snoitapocnys deredrosid
.yltnetni gnihctaw
,semit erom evif ksat eht staeper rykeS
,ruf nat ni derevoc si ydob ralucsum tey ehtil siH
.erop yreve morf egduls suorohci ,yhtrae ,krad erom neve eduxe ot snigeb htiarwegduls eht ,esnopser nI
”.eb tsuj s’teL .won thgir
- egdod enola tel ,hctiwt ot emit sah ylerab nrohT
,ti od t’nac eh mih sllet tI
.tnahc eht fo mhtyhr emas eht ot ylraluger gninnips strats ti dna
,pohskrow s’regdab eht esnohplA ni sevlesmeht dnif raeb tesyvaeh eht dna xof llat eht
,mih mlehwrevo ot snigeb ytisnetni ehT
.ecaps efas ,emoh weN
.drabbacs sti fo eerf ti sllup nrohT sa sgnir drows trohs a fo dnuos ehT
,dnopser t’nseod rykeS
.tcatnoc eye gnikam ton
,tesnus snetaerht nus gnineve eht sa ,yad taht retaL  ~ .gnis sluos
.ecafrus detecaf s’enotstraeh eht ot dehcatta llits tub tuoba gnivom
.ecarbme s’nrohT ni shtaerb peed erom wef a sekat rykeS
.yltneg ,flow eht sksa regdab eht ”?pu teg uoy naC“
,mrof sraeF .sraor
.etihw ot kcab der eht snrut
,xof gnikoolno ehT
,staeb tnadrocnoc eht gniyfilpma no sesucof tnetni siH
.tcatnoc eye gnikam ton llits ,sdnopser raeb eht ,esuap gnol a retfA  .sksa eh
,nrohT .cnys ni yllanif
,ereh ecneulfni citenik dleif-raen eht s’taht ,ho
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.swap sih htiw ecaf s’rykeS spuc nrohT
.nwod stis eh sa snworf regdab ehT
.yrros m’I .niaga ti did I
.flow lacinahcem gninrael-kciuq a htiw dnuora gninnur fo sesserts reltneg eht rehtar tub ,elttab fo ytisnetni eht htiw ton dellif yad a retfa
.rentrap sih ta pu skool nrohT
,ecnelis detsuahxe ni hsaw yehT
did woH“ .nrohT ot snrut regdab ehT
.htolcniol sih ot spirts neht
,detpurretni xof ehT  ”-eht morf sdleif ecneulfni eht yfilpma ot etinavlys dedeen eh dias esnohplA“ .sdrawkcab gnireggats ti gnidnes ,tsehc s’htiarw rehtona ot erauqs ekirts mlap a otni thgiew sih sworht eh sa
.skniht eh ,krow dluoc sihT
,shtiarwegdulS eht revo yrotciv rieht htiw htob elbatrofmoc
.seye sih llif sraet dna ecaf s’raeb eht no sworg elims eguh A
.tug thgit ,dnuor ,gib a dna sgel dna smra tliub ylivaeh htiw ,dliub retuots a tog s’rykeS
.enots der eht ot kcab noitnetta sih gninrut
.hcnebkrow eht no tuo meht gnidaerps dna lufwap egral a gnibbarg ,kcas eht ot seirruh raeb ehT  .syas regdab eht
”?noitca ni ti ees ot tnaW
.retnec eht dnuora gnitibro
.elyts euqinu a hcus sah regdab ehT
.wolf sraet eht sa
”?sretsnom erom oN“
,tsehc s’tsaeb-egduls eht ta yldetaeper sehsals dna sraor eh sa ytisnetni htiw nrub seye s’rykeS
.tnemom a sekat nrohT
.ydob s’flow lacinahcem eht ot neht ,nrohT ot kcab esnohplA morf skool rykeS  ”?od
.rethgual htiw ylnepo lwoh ot snigeb ohw ,nrohT fo tnorf ni spets eH
”?em raeh uoy oD .floW“
”?neppah ot desoppus taht si
.esle gnihtemos dnif ll’ew
~   .senaw thgilyad eht fo tsal eht sa riap gnicarbme eht dnuora selppir retaw looC  ”.taht ekil d’I“
.esnohplA dnuora ylizal lriws dna sreniatnoc rieht morf esir sebut dna sraeg suoirav ,sevlehs eht morF
.ynorhcnys tcefrep ni era mhtyhr der eht dna mhtyhr neerg eht litnu
.noitisop otni spans hcae dna
.sebor sih
,psiw eht rohcna sepahs gnirutpac eht sa der wolg swalc siH
.llaw evac eht stcapmi ti sa esirprus ni snepo htuom gnippird stI
.tnurg a htiw roolf eht no stis regdab ehT
.ereh eb ot dalg tsuj yllaer s’ohw
?thgir ,regna eht htiw od ot esoohc uoy tahw si tnatropmi s’tahW
.flow laref tluda na fo ezis eht tuoba ,deggel-ruof
.seye sih sesolc dna elbat eht evoba wap sih sdloh eH
,epahs segnahc enotstraeh eht nihtiw thgil ehT
.won ylnepo elims daorb a gniraew s’regdab ehT
.dedolpxe meht fo emoS
,seirraH nomoloS yb
.esnohplA ot tuo gnidloh neeb dah eh hcihw
,doog gnihtyna ekam reven ll’eh tahT
.yfitnedi ot nigeb t’nac I secneuqes nezod a era ereht dna...“
.desserpmi em roloc ,lleW“
,sgniws ffatS .hsals sdrows
.tuo sllup eh sa skrims xof eht
.noitazilaer htiw ediw og seye s’raeb ehT
.etihw wolg ot nigeb swalc sih dna
.htaerb a sekat raeb eht sa sessap tnemom A
,senots xis rehto eht dna
.ti revo sessap eh sa enots hcae fo ecnanoser eht sleef eH
,on yllacinhceT“
.dnuora kcits ot nosaer hguone naht erom s’taht
,dnuorg eht ot spmuls flah rewol dedderhs sti litnu
,senots suoiverp eht lla morf smhtyhr eht sleef eH
seirraH nomoloS yb
”!meht tuohtiw uoy dniheb gniees yrt uoy ,llew ,haeY“
.teem seye riehT .sllaf wap ehT
,mhtyhr nwo sti sah etinavlys eht ,ereht dnA
.sesucof dna ygrene ihc sih sretsum eh sa
,erutaerc eht fo tsehc eht otni sknis ti sa dnuos hcleuqs gniyfsitas a sekam reggad hcaE
?sretsnom evac ytrid gnithgif ylno efil ruo sI
”,em llet uoY“  .sksa eh
.seye neerg s’nrohT otni thgiarts skool eh ,enots eht no llits regnif sih htiw ,nehT
;seye sih snepo esnohplA
.yaw siht ni secneuqes eht enibmoc ot thguoht evah reven dluow eH
,yas ot fi sa serutseg dna worbeye na sesiar eH
.sneppah tI .yrgna steg enoyrevE
eert ybraen a no gnuh dna naelc stnemrag rieht htiw
,eson gniwolg-llits a dniheb morF
.senots eht htiw stcaretni hcnebkrow eht fo ecafrus eht ni ygrene enotstraeh laudiser ehT
.dnuora ffats sih snips eh sa stnurg noinapmoc raeb ylrub ybraen sih
.ecafrus detecaf hguor eht yb senil cirtemoeg otni detcarfer
,ecafrus eht morf yawa hcni na tuoba taolf ot
.mih no tceffe gib a dah weivretni boj elttil taht ekil skooL
.evom t’nseod dna
~  .retal ti tuoba mih ksa ot erus ekam ot evah dluow nrohT
.ecaf s’regdab eht no tnemegaruocne eltneg eht gniees
,sredluohs sih no ruf eht sbur nrohT sa retaw looc eht ni kcen sih ot pu stis rykeS
.edisni enotstraeh eht seltsen dna
.mih ediseb ria eht ni sgnah tsim thgirb fo duolc A
.htlif detalumucca eht rednu elbisiv ylerab si cirbaf esraoc eht fo neerg krad ehT
.flow wen eht teerg ot drawrof spets raeb ehT  ”?tol a siht od uoy oD
rentrap sih nioj ot
.esnohplA ot skool rykeS
;thgir dna tfel seilf ti sa sehsalf drows trohs s’nrohT
”.rykeS ,kool resolc a teg emoC“
.ti pots t’nac uoY
.gur nrow eht gninroda riahc ysae enol eno
niaga tuhs ezeeuqs seye s’rykeS ”?uoy s’ti fi tahW
,htaerb sih rednu sesir ylwols tnahc A
.teef ruof sti no ylikahs dnats dna gnitoof sti dnif ot smees ti
.gnitnahcne rof kcank a hcus htiw esle enoyna tem reven ev’I“
.ssenkrad eht otni sreep eh sa
.eulb mid a ot edecer sroloc tesnus eht fo tsal ehT
.kcab eht fo elddim eht ni enots etinavlys eht no walc eno dna
”.dekrow ti ekil skooL .og ew erehT“ .htaerb detsuahxe ,gnol a tuo stel eH
,senots eht revo wap sih sesolc rykeS ,yltnatiseH
.laem s’gnineve rieht gnihctac
.ynapmoc tneserp s’rehto hcae htiw dna
.skaerb noitartnecnoc s’rykeS sa ecnetsixe fo tuo skniw seye fo olah lacigam ehT
.elihw a rof no evil ot hguone evah ll’ew ,boj siht morF
egnarts ni gnillup dna gnihsup
.tsiwt dna trid eht otni knis swalc raer s’rykeS
,esnohplA ta skool eH
.ecafrus eht ot esolc oot raf gnileef egar degnit-lohocla fo selcyc dlo sih
.sworruf worb sih ,esolc seye siH
.drawtuo toohs syar der dna
.mih no llot reggib a sekat boj yreve smees ti tub
.etator ot nigeb dna edisni sraeg htiw hsem sraeg eht dna
.til erif ,dehctip tneT
,decalp yletaciled ,sebut wef a dna sraeg erom wef A
.sretsnom dum lufwa esoht fo erom rof tuokool eht no saw I
yllautca ot sraeppa ti won tub strap eraps fo elip a ekil dekool erofeb taht ssarb dna rehtael fo paeh a ot
.yltneg syas regdab eht ”,niaga yrT“
,tcelfer yeht sa etihw wolg slipup sih
”enotS dna traeH fO“
”,htuom ym ni tog emos ,sdog ,hO“
.enots eht fo ecafrus eht otni dehcte sevlesmeht laever senur nedlog fo senil niht ,ni snael eh sA
.htxis eht retfa nrohT ot revo skool esnohplA dna
,niaga noitnetta gniyap strats ylneddus ohw ,nrohT
.dnopser t’ndid meht fo emoS
~ .nrob evol ,nioj sluoS
,roolf eht no tops a ot revo ti sgnirb dna
.timda ot erac d’I naht regnoL“ .tnedive etiuq
,senots eht no gnikrow si rykeS elihw yltnetni regdab eht sehctaw nrohT
,flow lacinahcem eht ot gnikil etaidemmi na nekat dah nrohT
”.yaw siht ees ot reisae ,ti htrow s’tI
,nrohT ta skool eH
”.ydduB .yeh ,yeh ,yeH“
.tis sdneirf ,dekooc dooF
.retteb tol a s’eno siht ,og sezoo kciht sa ,lleW“
.esnohplA no sucof dna ,won hctiwt seye neerg-eulb ehT
.thgir mees t’nseod tahT
.eson sih morf thgil eht ni gnimaelg latem krad eht ,mra tfel lacinahcem sih pu sdloh esnohplA
.taes sih setacav eh sa
.aedi eht ta selims raeb ehT
.drawrof spets dna noitaluclac kciuq a seod raeb ehT
.ni edaw ot aera ydnas a dnif yeht sa ecnatsid eht ni ylwols sevaw dleif ssarg rebma llat ehT
.sgurhs tsuj xof eht dna
,sdrawpu stsrub dna ecnalg a htiw gninoitisop sih skcehc eH
,esnohplA ot meht sgnirb dna senots tnanoser tsom neves eht pu srehtag raeb ehT
”,enif eb ylbaborp ll’uoY“
.seye neerg-eulb gniwolg s’flow eht otni skool raeb ehT
.mih ta pu skool raeb eht nehw noisserpxe ciots a ot kcab ylkciuq sehctiws ohw
,rehto hcae rof ereht neeb
”?ebyam ,yhcnurC .ti yas ot woh wonk t’nod I …sleef ti
.enotstraeh eht htiw pu senil mhtyhr s’etinavlys eht erehw tnemom a s’ereht ,sdnoces wef yrevE
,enips eht gnola meht fo owt
.noitasrevnoc eht eunitnoc ot esnohplA ta kcab skool eh erofeb regral ylthgils os reve sworg nirg sih dna nrohT ta revo skool rykeS
.ria eht ni sepahs mrof ot strats dna
,moor egral eht fo retnec eht ni stis hcnebkrow s’regdab ehT
.tols hcae ni enots a secalp dna drawrof sevom raeb ehT ”.yako ,mU .hO“
,hcum os sevol eh taht efil gnirutnevda eht pu evig ot ydaer ,llits tey
.detcartsid gnimoceb yb nekat d’eh ksir sselerac eht gnizilaer ,toh worg skeehc siH
,esnohplA htiw sesrevnoc eh sa selims raeb ehT
.yenruoj wen siht no
,skniht eh ,ti tog tsomlA
”.em ta kooL .ydduB .yeh ,yeH“
.dnim sih sraelc dna seye sih sesolc eH
.dnim ot emoc ,seno rednet eht dna stnemom esnet eht htob
.elddim eht ni thgir ygrene fo eroc der a s’ti litnu
.evac eht fo traeh eht drawot nap dna krep srae sih
.taebtraeh sih snekciuq won eman sih fo thguoht eht
.nur lluf a ta gnimoc erutaerc ladepib yvaeh yrev a ekil sdnuos tahw sraeh eH
llaw evac eht otni gnirettalps dna gniylf rohci kcalb erom gnidnes ,worb sih fo ffo egduls dna taews eht sepiw ylkciuq raeb ehT
raeb eht morf ylper eht emac
.seye sih snepo eH
,ecaf sih no tsugsid spahrep
,egattoc egral ylriaf a yllautca s’tI
.snworf dna ti sees eh sa nediw seye s’rykeS
- strap fo sevlehs nopu sevlehs yb llams raeppa ot edam
.ediced ot emit on sdeen tub
,moor eht ni pu skcip ezeerb A
.noisseccus kciuq ni sreggad owt sgnilf eH
,dellup steg ti dna
.syas kool sih ,”emit siht toN“
.tnemom a rof esolc seye siH
.selims regdab ehT
,etavitca ot ykcirt erom ylbaredisnoc ti sekam ti ,haeY“  ”-
,seiromem mirg htiw dellif ylneddus si dnim s’rykeS .nwod gut htuom sih fo srenroc ehT
.sllaw enots eht ffo seohce maercs delgrug rehtona dna sehsalps egdulS
”.deksa I yrros ,dnimreveN“
.ecaf sih no elims detnetnoc a htiw rennid sih tae ot seunitnoc xof ehT
.sdaeh rieht ni ohce meht neewteb snoitasrevnoc dlo fo snezoD
tuons derruf-kcalb esiwrehto sih no riah etihw eht
.guh a rof ni raeb eht sllup nrohT sa htmraw eltneg ot yaw sevig retaw looC
”enotS dna traeH fO“   yojne esaelP
.rohtuA eht yb daeR  .yrruFoS no
.gnikcatta s’eh mohw sezilaer rykeS sa raef ot nrut seye dellif-egaR
.niht dna kciht hguorht ,yddub siH
”?tset a taht saW“ ,skniht xof ehT
,tnemom elgnis taht nI
.egnahc a rof emit s’tI
”?ereht ni gnitseretni esle gnihtyna eeS“
,skniht dna yvarg eht ta nwod skool eH
.thgil etihw erup a htiw wolg ot strats eson sih fo pit eht dna
.tnenamrep erom gnihtemos etaerc ot tnaw ew tub
.sbos teiuq sih htiw selppir revir eht sa
,ylregnig loots eht no nwod stis rykeS
- enotstraeh eht no walc eno secalp eh ,ylevitatneT
,seunitnoc nrohT
.ecaf sih no kool knalb eht sezingocer nrohT
.esaeler dna llif swolleb maets sti sa nwod dna pu sesir tsehc stI
.seye s’nrohT otni yltnegru skool eh tub
,rykeS ta yltnetni gnikool si esnohplA
.tib elttil a stfil traeh sih dna
,yllacitengam tsomla
,sdnopser esnohplA
.noisufnoc htiw worran ylneddus neht seye siH
,)dedulcni htolcniol s’nrohT(
”.srehto eht htiw ti od uoy ees s’teL
?siht gniod peek ot evah ew oD …tsuj I“ syas neht
.evac eht morf detcelloc d’yeht skcor neerg eht fo skcas egral owt gniyrrac osla won raeb eht
- hguoht ,ffo sreggad eht epiw ot emit on s’erehT  ”.hgU“
,dnas yrd eht ni meht sevael dna lehctas dna shtaehs nopaew ,romra rehtael sih selkcubnu nrohT
.drawni nrut sthguoht s’nrohT
”.uoy hcaet ot yppah eb d’I
”,gniht a ees t’naC“
,kool lufthguoht a rykeS sevig esnohplA   ”?ecitnerppa na no gnikat redisnoc thgim uoy kniht uoy od
,nwod gnikooL .pop a sraeh eh dna
,enotstraeh eht fo eslup eht leef nac eH
,gnorw gnihtemos gnisneS
.deen yreve s'rehto hcae ot gnidnet
.kcab sih ssorca gnihsag swalc fo niap eht sleef eh sa raor peed a otni snoitisnart dna stuc ecnetnes siH
.hcleuqs a htiw tuo sreggad sih sllup dna shtiarw detaefed eht fo eno fo tsehc eht no dnats ot revo sklaw dna
.tuo sgnah eugnot rehtael a dna snepo waj latem ehT
.sraey eht revo derujni neeb s’eh erehw riah gnissim fo senil racs lareves htiw
,ylsuorocedni strons ,seye sih snepo rykeS
,esnohplA ta pu skool dna ,htaerb a sekat
.htmraw s’rehto hcae otni gnixaler
.wolf ot nigeb sraet sa tuhs ezeeuqs seye s’raeb ehT
.tcesretni senil enur eht erehw sucol cificeps a eb ot skool tahw ni pit walc hcae htiw
”?eb…tsuj dna xaler nac ew erehw ecalp a dnif ew lliw nehW
.redluohs s’rykeS sehcuot xof ehT
.sdnuow rieht morf doolb htiw dexim secalp ynam ni
.taht dna yaw siht gninnap srae
,ereh yppah si rykeS fi tub
.ecaf sih no elims gib a htiw
.ti tuoba daer ylno yllaer ev’I ,lla ta toN“
.eno rehtona fo tsehc eht otni erauqs thgil etihw-neerg fo maeb enif a gnisaeler
,srettuts noitom stI .der
,senil tneb eht snetfos
”.emit revo nehtgnerts ot tnemtnahcne eht gnilbane
,raeppa sepahs revel dna sraeg fo stnih eugaV
.erutaerc derevoc-egduls eht drawot snur eh sa syas xof dedooh llat eht
”.seye ekans ypeerc esoht gnisu pots ll’eh ebyam dnA
,sdnuos gnihsiuqs duol yb detautcnup si pets hcaE
,sksa eh rykeS ot ,nehT
.tuo taht detniop uoy dalg m’I !ahA“
,rethgif gnizama na si dneirf tseb siH
.spord taeb ,teem seyE
”.dedeen uoy seno eht erew yeht derugif I os ,hsup eht yfilpma ot demees seno esehT
.yad eht fo esruoc eht revo htgnerts deniag flow eht sa rehtegot deyalp dah owt eht dna
.roloc neerg-eulb a wolg ot trats ylwols yeht sa seye s’gniht-flow eht otni serats esnohplA
gniruces epor eht seitnu eh dna ,sgniht s’nrohT ot txen llordeb rieht dna ,sehcuop ,ffats sih ,skcor fo skcas eht spord rykeS
”,yug gib ,enif er’uoY“
,nekaew ot noitom gnirettuts eht sesuac stsirw sih fo tsiwt derobal ,wols A
...“  .meht gnola gnidneb ytilaer fo cirbaf lanoisnemiditlum eht
”.ti ekil t’nod yllaer ,yllaer I
ksa ot fi sa kool a mih sevig regdab ehT
.demahsa ,yawa snrut raeb ehT
,seye sih sesolc raeb ehT
.desiar sworbeye s’regdab ehT
”.gnimocni tog eW ?rykeS yeH“
.ylwols gnitnahc llits s’ohw ,regdab eht ot skool dna
”?ta gnikool I ma tahW“
.hcnebkrow eht morf pu gnitteg ,smialcxe eh ”!suineg s’tahT“
.snoitcerid lla ni seilf kcuM
.sbreh dna ,slatsyrc ,slarenim fo selpmas detros gniniatnoc tsom tub ytpme emos
.kcab s’esnohplA dniheb scra
,daeh s’htiarw a ffo spol ylnaelc drows trohs siH
…evac eht ni kcaB“
,swap sih ni latsyrc eht sbarg eh ,spool eht gninethgiT
,ylsuoirobal ,snethgit tI
.nrohT eno ,raeb enO
,ylidaets ,ylwols tuB
”.ti evresed t’ndid taht gnihtyna truh t’ndid uoY
.flesmih ot ylteiuq selkcuhc eH
,enotstraeh eht ot esolc ti sgnirb dna dnah eno htiw ti sekat regdab eht ,sucof sih gnisaeler tuohtiW
.roolf eht no sraeppa sucum suonimul fo liart esraps A .ezeens esnetni na sesaeler dna hcnebkrow eht morf yawa ylkciuq snrut eh dna
.ypeerc elttil a s’ti ,eruS
.eerf kaerb ot sthgif ti sa ecnesse citoahc sti gnidnib
,dnoces a rof sredisnoc rykeS
.ria eht otni gninnips ti gnidnes
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,daeh sih evoba yldipar setator seye delipup-tils ,neerg tneculsnart fo olah yltsohg A
stcapmi dewalc s’raeb eht esuaceb flah dna egduls ykcits eht ot eud flah llaw eht ot deulg gniyats flah reppu sti
,ygrene lacigam eht tcerid senil eht yaw eht leef nac rykeS
mrof evitcaretni na ni elat siht dnif nac uoY
.kcals og dna netfos ruf eht rednu selcsum esnet egral ehT
,ralucitrap ni eno sihT“
,srekram noitanimret etelpmocni eht htiw ,ecneuqes eht tuB
.nwod seid ezeerb eht dna
,deggaj snrut ylneddus enots eht morf gnitaidar thgil etihw fo spsiw eht fo enO
,srehto eht gnitsujda dna
.snethgit pirg siH
sluos ,mraw seidoB
?kcul s’rennigeb tsuj taht saW !dooG
.teem seidob rieht sa revir eht nwod ylizal stfird ruf rieht morf emirg eht fo tsal ehT
”?teg ot seno hcihw wonk uoy
.htaerb a sekat dna psiw demlac-won eht sesaeler raeb ehT
,pu gninil yllanif luos nwo sih fo smhtyhr eht sleef rykeS
.yawa stfird ekoms suonimul fo ffup a dna ,owt ni dekcarc sah enots kcen neerg eht
,nwo rieht no tcennoc sebut eht
.tsen sdrib ,prihc stekcirC
.etsat ydlom ,yhtrae eht tuo stips dna sgag eh
.ti otni enotstraeh eht srewol dna
,seye denrecnoc htiw syas
.nwod edils ot snigeb ti sa kcab ti gnisserp peek
.gnirehtag eht did rykeS !em ta kool t’noD“
.ruf dekac-kcum ’srehto hcae ot ees riap eht
”,srebmahc elttil eseht fo hcae ni og senots ehT“
.swap sih pu sdloh ,tif gnihgual sih spots yletaidemmi ohw ,xof ehT
,derahs ev'yeht serutnevda eht fo llA
,reilrae dessorc dah yeht revir eht fo erohs eht ta evirra raeb dnutor eht dna xof llat eht
.kcab s’raeb eht no sehsag gnol eht gninaelc ylregnig ,syas xof eht
,sebor rieht dna secaf rieht snroda kcum deird yllaitraP
”enotS dna traeH fO“ saw sihT
,ydob lacinahcem a eb
,thgif doog a fo tnemeticxe eht ssim ot emoc yam eh stcepsus xof ehT
”,yddub ,wolb wol a s’tahT“
.raeb eht fo tnorf ni stauqs dna dnuora sevom nrohT
,oi.hctI no
?emit txen tuoba tahw tuB“
.dehcterts swalc dna derab hteet ,ylkciuq snrut raeb ehT
.edaf sracs ,laeh sdnuoW