,hsinif ot ytilibani na
.ereht ruf hcae fo ytilauxes eht rof tcepser tsomtu setartsnomed taht
xes gnitamilbus ot edisnwod laer ylno eht
pot doog a eb ot sthguoht ym ni pu depparw oot neeb ev'I
,rae sih otni oom I nehT
,tsum etteuqite ,woN
.llub gib ,tuls elttil ruoy m’I“
:yxes os si eciov taht dna
.buc ,sevlac sih htiw ylleb ruoy llif annog s’yddaD“
,dna ,regae ,yldneirf
,elzzum yerg ym etipsed ,taht uoy erussa I ,woN
tey dnA .tuanortsa na ot era srehcaerp htraE talf eht sa tniauq sa si noitanmednoc s'moT .tS ,em oT
.esihposolihp ot emit ym si siht—
.moT .tS fo kniht ot emit eht ton yllaer si siht tuB   .lasuora ,llew
.tfos tib a og ot nugeb ev’I hguoht—
.retseylop dna nottoc eht hguorht ehtaerb ot selggurts eh dna
sllab sih morf pu dnah ym gnirb I
,em ekil ,saw saniuqA samohT esuaceb
!retfa yhposolihp daer uoy tel ll’I  ?niarb ,esaelP
,dlrow yzarc siht dnA   .ti gniod
.yltfos daeh sih ekorts I    .hctiwt
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
tuo pop I erofeb kcoc ym no setteuorip eh ,tnemom a rof
.emit eht rof gniksa saw I ekil gnidnuos pu dedne I ,mlac erom eb ot gniyrT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.em rof regnad a eb dluow taht ,esruoc fO
,snoissap gnisoppo snoissap fo
si raeb siht ;flesym ot elims I
,efilretfa na rof dnuorg-gnitset erem a regnol on si dlrow gnizama siht taht snaem
.semit etairporppani tsom s'efil ta pu emoc syawla snoitseuq etairporppa tsom s'efiL   regguR .P .B yb
.neht ,yldab taht detcarevo t’nsaw ti sseug I ,lleW
tfos og I taht hguone moT .tS fo kniht
.dlrow siht ni esoprup ym gnihsilpmocca ma I ekiL  .etelpmoc
?ti otni evol ruo dna ,noissap ruo
?yb dekcuf eb eh dluow esle ohw dnA
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.tuo emoc ot gnilggurts rewsna eht leef I
.ssa sih otni peed spih ym gnivird
,hcruhC cilohtaC eht ot tnemssarrabme na sniamer dna ,drusba si aedi yrev eht esruoc fO
enihcam gnikcuf emos ekil gnitsurht yllacinahcem neeb tsuj ev'I—
.sehsitef ym lla wonk ot mees t’nseod eh fi nmad dna ,syas eh
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
!thginot neve rO  .worromot mih yb deticxe eb nac uoy tuB  .saniuqA yb deticxe er’uoy taht teg I
.reel a htiw yas I
evila tlef I ekil tsuJ
.smottob regae fo enil a evah ydaerla seno rehto wef eht dna ,ereh spot yag ylno eht fo eno m’I
.nerdlihc erom wef a sevas dna
?lla kcuf siht sI
,retcnihps sih sezeeuqs dna slworg eh dna
.lasuora dna niap fo pley a gniticile dna mih gnikram
.pot ot detnaw I esuaceb demottob I
.gnilgnit daehkcoc ym
:ytilauxesomoh no noitisop ddo s’hcruhC cilohtaC eht erofereht dna
!yadretseY !won morf sruoh owT  !worromoT
.osrot ediw ,gnorts taht otni ti bur dna
kcen sih fo kcab eht yb mih ezies I
.mottob tcefrep a hcuS
.moT .tS fo gnikniht fo enutrofsim eht dah I erofeb—
litnu yllacinahcem kcuf flesruoy tel tsuJ
:citecsa on m’I
,noitseuq ni sraeppa tnesnoc hcihw ni enecs na gnivresbo nehw
.enon htiw ma I ereh tey dna ,yzarc si rewsna s’moT .tS
.nosrep doog a si srehto dna dlrow eht rof secifircas sekam ohw nosrep A
.tuls tneidebo ym eb ot stnaw eh dna
:nuf tsuj t’nsaw xeS
.taht naht tnatropmi erom gnihton saw ereht dna
!pu tuhs t’now tsuj tI  .semitemos ,niarb yM
,snekcalb dlrow sih sa revo ezalg ot nigeb seye sih ees nac I
?tnemom eht yojne dna retal litnu saniuqA tuoba tegrof ot tnaw I t'ndid ,on ,tiaw—
,raeb siht morf erusaelp ym gnikat yb tuB
”gniS yretsyM eht hselF siH fO“
,sllab deniard htiw emoh og ylpmis I lliw ,siht retfA
.niaga pu dekcuf I ,timmad ,tuB
.noitcus fo pruls eht dna noitcafsitas fo shgis eht ot gninetsil
.ygro yrruf a si siht :ti ecaf s’teL
arhteru rieht nihtiw sdor leets kciht gnicalp yeht eb
:suoinegni saw noitulos s’saniuqA
.rof dellac si ecifircas nehw semit era ereht ,seY
dnah rehto ym htiw pih sih barg I
.ega nredom eht otni
.xes yag evah ton tub ,yag eb nac uoy
;eldnah rettiwt a dna ,yromem dnof a
suonitarek ym ,kcen eht yb mih sbarg dnah rehto yM .dnah eno htiw
,daeh sih spolevne wollip ehT
,spley eH  .drah ,ezeeuqs I
.cinap tnangats a ni deliocer dna modeerf fo etsat a decneirepxe ohw ,dlonrA wehttaM on m'I
,stuokrow gnitnurg eht ,seodlid eht ,sgnils eht ,raeg ehT
tolipotua no ti od ot em dewolla evah ot mees gnikcuf fo sraey ynam ym ,yllufknahT
…ma I won dna raeb taht gnikcuf tuo dehguot I
ffilc a ffo llaf ot tuoba si ohw nosrep a evas ot bulc flog a gnisu
,psag ot seirt eh
ecalp retteb a dlrow eht ekam ot yaw a gnidnif neht dna—
,tuls tneidebo ym eb ot mih tnaw I  .sih ecnahne I
,nepo era seye sih dna
,dna ,eruliaf eht rof em emalb ylreporp dluow eh neht
.won raeb siht kcuf nac I os .egdelwonk eurt evah suht dna ,gnihton wonk I
,rentrap rieht fo klim tsaerb eht gniknird ro
,hgis a gnisserppuS   .mih kcuf tsum I
secitcarp lauxes eht no sucof ot
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
,ygro na fo elddim eht ni enola tfel eb dluow eH
.noitcnufsyd elitcere daelp neht dna
.erised ot erised gnihctam fo emag a si ti
.yaw gnorw eht siht tuoba gniog m'I ebyaM
.erusaelp on meht gnirb taht
,dnuor sih gnikorts dnah ym ,tam eht no dekan yal ew nehw ,tuo gnikam detrats ew erofeb ,dnA
sruoivaheb lauxes dragersid ylpmis lliw retcarahc fo sruf
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
niap fo ssih thgils a otni snrut taht tub
,dehsauq ylluf neeb sah gnignirbpu evitavresnoc erom ym
tnaw ew tahw gnidnif tuoba si ytilaroM
.esilaer I neht dnA
!gnitanicsaf si saniuqA  .ti pleh t’nac I
sredluohs ym no sgel sih ecalp I
,dellifluf leef I dna
.em sa detrevrep sa tsomlA  .raeb ykniK
.erusaelp ym rof mih gnisu ma I tahT
pu ti kcus ylpmis tsum eh tub
,larommi ylbirroh eb dluow
.)noitaercorp rof ylno saw ti dedivorp(
.neppah reven dluow taht tuB     .moT .tS tuoba
,liat a fo buts elttil sih sgaw eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
slarom ruo dna slaog ruo rof serised ruo gniniartser tuoba ton si ytilaroM
.tca dercas a saw noitaercorP
?erusaelp erem ot efil ym fo hcum os detoved yllaer I evah tuB
.yrros m’I    .saniuqA samohT
;emag mus-orez a t'nsi efil ,tuB
,gnitirw ym ot yenom dna ygrene taht lla detoved I fi
serised ym etagenba ot saw od ot gniht larom dna reporp eht ,eroferehT
,deifsitasnu flesym dnif I tey dnA
noitaercorp rof edam era slatineg ruo esuaceb live si xes yag ,suht dnA
raeh ot srekoolno ruo rof hguone duol—
,yroeht s'saniuqA rednU
”,buc ,won enim si efil ruoY“
,mih otni peed kcoc ym mals I
,toidi na saw moT .tS ,eruS
?ekil skool ti tahw taht t’nsi ,yllacigol dnA
.efil fo trap tnatropmi na si erusaelp taht eurt si ti ,sey
?ecalp retteb a dlrow eht gnikam ot ,gninrael ot
.seye sih fo tuo og ot gnitrats si tsul eht taht seciton niarb ym fo trap emoS
segatnavda sti evah seod ega—
...sppa no tneps sruoh eht
hselF siH fO“:yojne esaelP
,raeb eht otni peed gniggid sregnif suonitarek ym
.llab a gnittih si esoprup s'bulc flog a sa
?msilihin citsinodeh ecarbme ot
”.raeb sih gnikcuf htiw hguorht og dna
noitaercorp ton si xes yag dna
.skniht saniuqA revetahw ,yllarom gnitca si eh
:doog gnileef tsuj naht erom s’ti tuB
,ytinummoc yrruf eht ni emoh ta tsom sleef eh ,sirraH .I.D
,tam eht otni elzzum sih gnimmals
.ni yaw sti skrow daehkcoc talf ym sa
”gniS yretsyM eht hselF siH fO“
gnitcarevo suoiverp ym xif ot yrt dna ,eenk eno ot og I
fo trap neeb sah eh hcihw
.srehto fo secitcarp eht ton egduj dna
.pu ti ssap tonnac ylpmis I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
larommi ni tuo gnidolpxe serised pu-delttob ruo fo regnad eht si
.ti sesrodne llits hcihw
,ydob ym hguorht llor—tnemllifluf dna—
.raeb eht ta nwod kool I
,esoprup s’eno htiw ecnadrocca ni noitca si noitca thgir fi taht
,ssefnoc tsum I hguohT
ssa sih tsniaga gnisserp daehkcoc ym
.won enim s’eh dnA  .tcefrep
.erom ekam ot trihs riah a raew ton deen I taht tsiser ot slive laer hguone era erehT
,pu hcra spih siH
yllufhturtnu ton—gnimialc
.murtnat a gnivah dlihc a ekil redro yreve tuohs yeht os dna
.elaK dna adgaD ,spup sih dna ,enahpetS ,nettik sih htiw adanaC ,awattO ni sevil regguR .regguR .P .B yb
,dnah taht htiw kcen sih fo kcab eht yb dennip mih peek I elihW
;kcen sih otni peed etib dna drawrof nael I
:nac ruf a dnuos tseteews eht tuo sevig eH
,desu eb ot dednetni erew yeht yaw eht seidob ruo gnisu erew eW
.desolc esac ,og ew erehT
.niks sih otni peed gniggid sregnif
,roolf eht ot knis spih siH
gnivol dna sselfles s’ti fi ediced t’nac I dna ,elims ddo na s’tI  .elims I
.gnitirw evila leef I ekil tsuJ
,kcoc ym dnuora sehcnelc ssa siH
;erusaelp citsinodeh fo stnemom wef a rof tsuj si yllaer troffe siht lla dna
:flesmih swonk llub dlo sihT
.citsidas dna hsifles ro
,sbus dna smoD fo
erusaelP  .em htiw gniraor
,yddaD em llac sbuc etuc eseht lla
.pih sih dna kcen sih yb em otni mih gnillup ,tnap I
,eman lagel sih rednu noitcif elggum setirw eh hguohT
.lortnoc ym rednu s’eh swonk eh
.pu mih llif annog m’I
,deyebo eb lliw yeht taht ecnedifnoc eht evah t’nod ohw seiddaD rehtael erucesni esoht fo eno ekil dnuos I
,daeh ym fo kcab eht ot moT .tS fo sthguoht hsup I ,daeh sih evoba meht nip dna stsirw sih barg I sA
.enim emoceb mih dehctaw enoyreve elihw ma I llub eht ekil mih elpmart
,rof dekrow ev’I feiler fo dnik eht s’ti tub
?taht nialpxe I nac woH
.si noitca larom tahw suht dna esoprup ruo sediced doG
.won tub emit yna tsomla mih gnikcuf saw I hsiw yllaer ,yllaer I    .evila leef I
.tsurht yreve htiw tnurg a otni gninrut naom eht
”gniS yretsyM eht
.mih llif muc fo strups tsal eht sa spih ym gnikcub
,ydob toh ym looc ot yletarepsed gniyrt htuom ym fo tuo gnignah eugnot ym
,meht gnissentiw ruf a ot raeppa secitcarp lauxes ’sruobhgien a errazib woh rettam oN
?yhposolihp tuoba kniht ot deen I esuaceb
,esu gnilfirt naht erom fo eb ot si ti fi
!efil ym fo tser eht rof yad yrevE
.em ylpmiS  !stoidi era smottob taht toN
,em ta pu gnikool ,raeb eht si ereht dna ,seye ym nepo I os
.kcoc ym sdeen tsuj eH
,ydob gnorts gib ym no sevlesmeht egrog seye siH .fnu ,ecaf sih dnA
,mih egavar ot em detnaw eh woh em dlot eh
.mih otni gnimmals kcoc ym ot decuder si dna
,nwot fo tuo morf si eh ecnis
.thgim ym lla htiw si ti roF
,ot ffo mih ssap nac I pot rehto emos ereht sI
.kcab hcra kcen dna enips sih ekam taht niap dna erusaelp fo smsaps yb detpurretni ylno em fo noitarimda sih
ecalp teiuq a ot og ot tnaw od I ,lla ti etipsed
.syaw yhtlaehnu ro
.drah os muc yddaD edaM
.niarb ,kooL   !TIMMAD—
.ygro taht ta mih gnikcuf saw I elihw did raeb yxes taht ekil tsuj
!raeb siht ton ,efil fo gninaem eht dna saniuqA fo gnikniht eb ot desoppus m'I ,on ,tuB
”,yddaD em edisni sevlac ruoy tnaw I“
,sehtaerb eH ”,yddaD ,seY“
.6991 ecnis
,tnaw I taht gniht yreve rof taht snaem
?smaerd dna slaog sih morf senomroh sih etarapes t’nac ohw llub dezarc-xes a tsuj I ma ,ruf yerg ym etipseD
gnikniht ysub oot saw I esuaceb hsinif t’ndluoc tub raeb suoegrog a edisni gnimmuc ot esolc os erew I hguoht sa
,dediugsim era sgnileef ym taht ytilibissop eht redisnoc tsum I ?woh tuB
.efil sih fo trap gib a xes edam ohw trevrep tnaig a
.ylleb dna sdnah sih fo og tel dna ,regna dna noitartsurf ni tnurg I
.toidi na saw I ,dias I sA
,erusaelp eno gnirb taht
,saniuqA erofeb sraey derdnuh A
.sredluohs ym ezeeuqs sgel sih sa llews ylleb sih hctaw I
.sllab sih no stser dna ydob sih nwod sedils dnah ym sa niarb sih otni kcab gniwolf doolb eht ,og tel I nehT
tnesnoc dias erusne
?pu taht evig I dluoc woH
,mih tsniaga sesserp tsrif kcoc ym sa noitapicitna fo esaeler eht morf htaerb yksuh eht
.sdnalg taews ym fo tuo ezoo selballys demrof-flaH
tenalp gnivil ,tnarbiv ,lufituaeb a tub
:tcejorp a gnihsinif ekil
.lacigam gnihtemos saw xes ,saniuqA samohT tniaS rof ,llits ,tuB
.slworg eh ”,em ekaT“
.sevlesruo trexe yam ew taht os xaler dna sevlesruo esuma ew
.esoprup ruo dnif ot ecnahc eht su sevig
,smottob delliflufnu edulcni smotpmyS
,dlrow ruo dna su detaerc doG ecniS
.tsrif elzzum ,wollip eht otni nwod mih ecrof dna
,esruoc fo ,dluoc I  .retal mih
?ma I mohw ot ecnereffid on edam siht fi sa efil ym ot kcab og I lliw
kcuf llits yllufepoh dna—
.stsirw ym barg ,enim yb dennip llits ,sdnah siH
na ta raeb suoegrog yletulosba siht otni kcoc war ym edils ot tuoba ,I taht si ti oS
ytisrevid eht roF
,gnorts si evird xes yM
.tnemyojne lautum dna
;ma I taht tsiehta
ygro na ta srennam fo kramllah eht si ti
nevaeh fo ecnesba eht taht esingocer I
,yas I sa tnedifnoc dna mlac gnieb yb
em fo diarfa tib elttil a
gel tfel sih barg I nehT
.elbaresim pu dne htob ll’ew dna ,pot rehtona kcuf ot yrT
,erusaelp fo naom daorb a otni snepo ssih sih sa tsuj em ot snepo ssa sih ,yllaniF
.htaerb fo tnap toh yreve htiw ylregae etarbiv sdrohc lacov yM
.repsihw I ”,buc dooG“
;ehtaerb ot gnilggurts s’eH
.rehtegot emoc raef dna ,tnemeticxe ,niap eht gniees
,si eh erehw srebmemer eh sa tsuj dna
,em gniyebo dna gnivres ni neht
.daetsni edirp ekat dna erusaelp ecnuoner yeht
,levon tsrif sih no krow ta drah si eH
.kcab sih fo evruc eht otni sesserp ylleb ym dna
,kcuf srehto gnihctaw ,gnikcuf
.noitazicartso fo gnihtaol-fles eht gnileef
,gnikniht gnizag-levan emos ni egludni ot deen a leef dna
,redrah dna repeed raeb siht kcuf ot ydob ym hsup I sa neve ,tey dnA
,revewoh ,taht dnoyeB
.ti od ot stnaw ohw eno eht m’I dna ,srae ym ot neve ,ekaf sdnuos tI
”.gnihton wonk uoy gniwonk si egdelwonk eurt ylno ehT“
mih ot kcab emoc ylwols dlrow eht hctaw I
,sruof lla no flesmih gnidnif ylnedduS
.yddaD rof buc doog a hcus erew uoY“—
.ecnetnes ddo na tahW
.mih otni edils dna
,rehposolihp dna tnias cilohtaC eht fo kniht—
,)erew ti hsiw I sa hcum sa(
.dlo taht si eh ,seY
.raeb siht no sucof em tel t'now tsuj taht saedi ykcaw s'moT .tS tuoba gnihtemos si ereht tuB
.tuo semoc gnihton tsomla tub
,spots gnikcub ym ,ylwolS
saw sihT.htob s’tI
.kcuf ,lleW    .gnidaelp seye
a sah eh ,taf dna elcsum htiw kciht—ygro
;ylleb sih fo ruf tfos eht kaos mucerp fo trups a eciton I
dna erusaelp dna niap htiw esraoh eciov sih ,syas eh
.doog sleef taht ,nmad dna
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.detceffa tuo semoc ti dna hcum oot ti ecrof I tub ,wol I
”.uoy edisni gniworg era sevlac s’yddaD gniwonk emoh og annog er’uoY
.won sraey ynam rof tliug tuohtiw gnigludni neeb evah I dna
.raeb suoegrog a hcus gnikcuf pu evig dluoc I enigami ot drah s’ti dna
.saniuqA samohT tuoba kniht dna
em tsniaga ssa sih gnillup dnah ym
,llew os gninaom si raeb siht dnA
:yllautca ,krow dluoc tahT
.enod s’raeb siht ecno kcocllub emos rof gnipoh
.hgis a sserppus I
,tnemeticxe htiw eciton I
.tey enod ton m’I tuB
,mih edisni peed deirub llits ,daehkcoc evitisnesrevo ym leef I dna
.dehsinimid ygrene ym dna desimorpmoc eb dluow tnemegduj ym taht
;snroh dna daeh ym revo ti gniws dna
ssap ti tel ot yrt I
,rebmemer t’nac I  ?I ma erehw
,eurt ,doG morf etarapes si doog
.flesym meeder tsum I
.edurc eb t'nod—seilleb evah od htob ew hguoht
.erom dna erom kcab sih gnihcra s’eH
,semag oediv dna tra dna scitilop dessucsid ew sa
,retawkcab cifitneics a otni dlrow eht ni noitazilivic decnavda tsom eht denrut dah ilazahG-lA
esrevinu eht ni doog si tahw ot resolc su thguorb ti
.gnikcuf yllacimhtyhr llits spih ym ,mih otni nael I
.esruocer on evah I ,salA
.emag mus-orez a sa ytilarom fo thguoht I
?wollahs tsuj I mA   .em sllifluf ti
”,gnivird detcartsid fo draeh ev’uoY“
,sehctiwt ssa sih tuB
”,hctib ym er’uoy swonk enoyrevE“
,daetsni ;yllis si
.gnikcuf detcartsid :suoidisni erom neve gnihtemos ,won tub“ ,yas dluow yeht
eganahpro gninrub eht otni segrahc ohw oreh eht si
.xes rof flesym trexe I tey dnA
,ecneluproc ywollip
.yrevocsid fo airohpue eht rof demirp era dnim dna ydob yM
.revuocnaV morf gnitisiv tsuj saw eh taht dias raeb eht taht rebmemer I dnA
,feiler sevig xeS
rae sih ni repsihw I   .tser ew ,erehT
mih nip nac I os mra etisoppo eht fo woble eht tsniaga mlap hcae ecalp neht
saniuqA fo thguoht I ,on ,oN
,7 ta gnitirw nageb regguR
.tnemom akerue eht erofeb trats neddus eht ekil srae ym stih ssa sih no sllab ym fo pals ehT
!?eromyna tnaw tneve I od tahW
.ria eht ni ssa sih dloh dna
,ees uoY  .ytilarom detareneg thguoht saniuqA tahw si hcihw ,gninaem latnemadnuf s’eno ot
.did I esuaceb ylpmis pot ot detnaw enoyreve demussa ylhsiloof I
.toidi na saw I esuaceb demottob syawla I
;aibohpomoh tnetal emos morf saniuqA fo gnikniht ton ma I roF
.etulosba ton saw doG neht ,doG edistuo detsixe doog fi tuB  .yrartibra saw ti neht ,doog detaerc doG fi rof
si yrots s’yadot dna
.ria eht otni gnisir sgel sih htiw kcab sih no gniyl ,raeb yfeeb ,yxes siht si ereH
.ton od ew gnihtemos dah
siht fo tuo teg dluoc I yaw yna fo kniht ot deirt niarb yM
.esoprup sti htiw ecnadrocca ni tca ot gniht a rof si doog tub
,eot ot niarb morf sreviuq ydob elohw yM
”,yddaD ,hctib ruoy m’I“
;gnixaler si noitabrutsaM
?hsitef kcuc a evah ot—
.won sllab ym ni gnidliub ti leef I rof ,lworg I ”buc ,uoy
?thgil-flah ni stsurht wef a rof lla
,yoj ruo gnirb t’nod ew fi ecalp retteb a dlrow eht ekam ew nac woh dnA
?won em rof ti siht si tub
.suoigilerri sa denmednoc neeb dah ti retfa
;redrah kcen sih ezeeuqs I
,gnisaercni erusserp eht leef I ,tsruht hcaE
.htiw roolf eht derevoc ev’yeht tam eht no nwod semoc eenk sih dna
,skeehc sih no sgnikram wobniar tsetuc eht sah eh
yaw a hcus ni tca ot fleseno sevooheb ti ,ygro na nihtiw fleseno dnuof sah eno nehW“
.em kaep dehcaer I yas ylpmis dluow yeht ,ygro na gnirud rehposolihp cilohtaC a yb detcartsid tog I taht sdneirf ym dlot I fI .hguoht ,tsenoh eb s’teL
!efil s'enoemos evas ot ti esu uoy erad woH
,on ,dnA  .syad ytisrevinu ym morf gnikcuf-raeb dna saniuqA neewteb snoitcennoc nettogrof-gnol hguorht gnirif ton si niarb yM
,nuf gnivah si esle enoyrevE
,rae sih otni oom neht ,keehc sih kcil I
;srennam sa llew sa scihte edulcni
.kcab llor daeh dna seye sih dna
.sih no spil ym kcol ot ni nael neht dna
.dnim ym fo kcab eht ni setarebrever ygro taht tuoba gnihtemoS
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,live fo gniht a emoceb sgnileef ruo dna taht od ew—
.saniuqA tuoba gnikniht evila leef I
.noitcif ot kcab gnimoc speek dna
.eriseD fo ytitnauQ ehT
.nwod mih gnittel m'I won dna—
.tcatni yltsom eb dluow ereh noitatuper ym
.hsifles eb dluow esiwrehto od ot—srieht teem nosrep rehto eht tel dna
,enim s’eh taht mih gnillet
,wohemos doog sa eb t'ndluow tsuj I taht leef I tey dnA
,htiaf naem t'nod I ,oN
.thgim ym lla htiw tsurht I sa neve
?mih yb desluper ton erew I hguoht sa ,yllanosrep taht ekat eh dluow hguohT
,live uoy era esoprup ruoy tsniaga tca uoy nehw ylnO
flesym gnisucxe yb noitacav sih gniniur rof elbisnopser flesym dloh yllaer I dluoC
.enim s’eh wonk ot mih tnaw I
,thguo dna si fo noitalfnoc yllis sih lla rof ,moT .tS
ylteews os snaom eh dna
.elbanoicsnocnu si tluser a hcuS
:siht no nettirw dah tsoP ylimE ylno fI
,repeed dna repeed ni edils ot kcoc ym  gnilliw
.eciton ot enog raf oot s'eh kniht I taht
,fo daetsni regna yb desuora eb dluow eh won thgir ,esruoc fo ,hguohT
”.buc ,drawer ruoy sa uoy edisni gniworg sevlac s’yddaD fo ynam os evah annog er’uoy dnA
.slaog rehto ym otni tup ot emit erom tol a evah ylniatrec dluow I
sih rof nwonk tnias eht s'eh esuaceb saniuqA tuoba kniht ton did I
ecneics ot rosrucerp eht—yhposolihp larutan thguorb eH
,raeb etuc taht htiw gnitrilf
,hself rednet sih otni  knis hteet talf ym leef I dna ,strap ruf eht
.yaw rehto on s'erehT
.ti gnirud tnegnat lacihposolihp driew emos no enog dah I taht tcaf eht etipsed ,nuf neeb dah tahT
.lasuora dna kcohs fo yrc a sevig eh
,em ot sgnoleb eh taht
;efil xes ym depleh sah ruf yerg eht
.erusaelp fo noisolpxe na htiw flesym drawer ot yad gnol a retfa kcab eil I
”.gnitanicsaf era srehposolihp cilohtaC dlo-raey 008 ,cibohpomoh skniht taht ytilanosrep gnirob ,suopmop a dna
.mih kcuf ot em rof gniggeb ylyoc ,enim otni kool seye siH
.won thgir raeb a gnikcuf m’I  .nettogrof dah I .tihS .…raeb siht edisni muc ot kcoc ym gnisu em ekil
?won mih gnikcuf eb ot evah I od yhW
?ytinutroppo siht teg em ekil tsinoitibihxe devarped ,dlo na seod netfo woH
,serutlucbus dna sebirt dna seiceps fo
.tnaw I taht sgniht pu evig tsum I ,retteb dlrow eht ekam ot em roF
tnemesuma rof krow dna sevlesruo trexe ot taht dias eltotsirA
ylleb mrif-tey-gnidleiy
,llub gnuoy drawkwa dna yhs a saw I nehw rebmemer I
ytilarom lacigol fo emotipe ehT
?xes gnivah pots ot erew I fi ,ssim I dluow tahW
”?buc ,ssa taht dnuop yllaer ot yddaD rof ydaeR“
deerb annog s’yddaD“   .lliw I ti ekat dnA
.sgninaem dna serusaelp sseldnuob htiw
?setarcoS a llup tsuj I naC
,redrah mih gnikcuf trats I
,ygro eht gnirud saniuqA samohT .tS fo kniht yam
,muc I ,ereht sruf tsom fo sdaeh eht snrut taht oom duol a htiw ,nehT
.drah em teg ot woh swonk eH  .kcuF  ”.llub
.sevil sselyoj ,ytpme dael ew dna
.mih fo pot no espalloc I dna
,sevlesmeht gnikorts dna gnihctaw ,smottob rehto era em dnuora sruf rehto ylno eht ,oN
.ti ekat ot em stnaw esle enoemos
,daeh sih evoba rehtegot smra sih gnirb I
.su ot nrut sdaeh wef a ees I dna
snaeporuE sdrawkcab eht gniggard saw sainuqA ereh dna
.s’rehtona evoba serised ym gnittup em eb dluow tI
:no em snrut yllaer taht ecaf sih s’ti tub ,toh gnikcuf os
,sredluohs lufrewop ,daorb yb demarf ylleb yldduc ,tfos
.srepsihw eh ”,yddaD ,uoy knahT“
,ezeeuqs I sa seye sih hctaw I
?efil laer ni tsixe snoitop obmih t’nod yhW  .timmaD
ruovaf otni kcab—
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,regguR .P .B yb
.won raeb siht gnikcuf em htiw draobno teg ot uoy deen tsuj I ,won thgiR
,yam gnideerb doog fo ruf a ,suht
scihte s’moT .tS dedracsid I evaH
,doG morf etarapes saw doog taht detartsnomed dah ,otalP
.elines tey ton ma I
.pirg ym hguorht kaeps ylerab nac eh esuaceb yksuh lla
od reven dluow I esruoc fo dna ,raeb yfeeb etuc a kcuf ot kcoc ym gnisu em sa dab sa s’tahT
,yhposolihp ni daer-ediw gnieb ,gnideerb doog fo ruf a ,woN