,tsrif ta sesroh narreT detropmi evisnepxe yrev draoba
sserd reh fo mosob eht tsniaga gnisserp stsaerb nwo reh
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,mosob ot hctorc reh morf pu ti gnillup
.shgiht dna specib reh ta seno eht erew lufesu ylsuoivbo sseL
,rebbur ro citsalp kcalb
,ssa reh revo gninepo llams a hguorht ti gnihsup
,krow reh dehctaw illaS
,rehtael htooms eht gnibbur
,noitcurtsnoc suoiruc a fo erew selkcub eht llA
.tsehc reh ssorca gnikaerc tius eht
.shgiht reh pu tius eht llup ot deunitnoc ehs sa sdaptoof reh ot ylthgil gnippord ,detnurg ilA ”,epoN“ ”?gniht
.detpmorp ilA ”?illaS“
.ti ot tcaer dluow illaS yldab woh gniwonk ylbaborp
ilA fo thgis eht morf flesreh tcartsid ot erom ,deksa illaS
,s'tius eht otni smra reh dekrow ehs nehT
sregnif dna bmuht reh neewteb dessorc taht sparts ni gnidne
,reh sdrawot denrut ilA   ”?taht si tahW“
,rennuts mlap reh fo retsloh mraerof eht delkcubnu neht dna
”?serutcip yna evah uoy oD
,yaD ecyoR ”rehtaeL deliO“
saw ti dias einaleM ydaliM oS“
,tiusecaps a ekil
,elbat ybraen a no tleb tnempiuqe reh gniyal
.sehtolc raluger raew em tel dna
,hcnebkrow s'ilA no tuo dial saw tahw was ehs sa trohs gnippots
”...em gnillac peek ot evah t'nod uoY .esuops ym er'uoy
kcab nexiv regnuoy eht gnisserp
”rehtaeL deliO“   :yojne esaelP
.ylthgirb dias ilA
saw sihT     .yllautnevE
,ti no nottub eno ylno saw erehT
tub taerg skool tI“
,tius eht fo tekcop llams yllauqe na morf tinu lortnoc etomer llams a koot neht
.sdap mlap reh ssorca dna
.ekam ot evisnepxe yllacifirret saw tI
,ylleb reh ot taorht reh morf gninnur lenap etihw a htiw kcalb saw hcihw
,denethgit ylneddus sparts fo dairym eht sa
.yrd ylneddus worg htuom reh gnileef ,deilper illaS
reh ni saw ehs revenehw sredrocer dediova syawla einaleM ydaL esruoc fO
,taoctsiaw reh nottubnu ot nageb ehs nehT
.niks dnoces a ekil ydob reh ot dedlom won tius eht
.anosrep nexiV deR remrof s’einaleM fo lobmys eht
.noitidart eht eunitnoc su tel ,snaem lla yb nehT“
tsirw eht ta sgninepo eht
dna stnemerusaem ym koot ehS
.suoiruc werg noisserpxe s’ilA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,pu kcab regnif reh thguorb illaS
,moor eht llif ot demees rehtael dna lio eht fo tnecs ehT
”?no ti yrt ot em ekil uoy dluoW“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.sresahc ssarg tsaf ylsuoiriled dna
,hcnebkrow eht fo egde eht no tas ehS
,gnihtolc dna raeg reh fo tuo gnippirts nageb dna
,denepeed gnihtaerb reh sa
,peed deyd rehtael fo edam
,gab liat a otni ssam yrruf eht gnivohs
.gninnirg ,deilper ilA
llup ot deunitnoc ehs sa drawtuo gnihtaerb
”?seitnap ruoy neve toN“
sgel reh neewteb dehcaer ilA sa
sebut citsalp raelc ynit htiw
.rehtie yas dluoc ehs esle hcum t'nsaw ereht yllautcA
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.tisiv ot desu walC telracS eht noitats a no pohs sdoog rehtael a sah ohw
,rekrowrehtael eht ,diacniK ssiM“ ”.edam llew s’tI“
,ilA dnuora smra reh gnipparw erofeb
,selkna dna stsirw reh ta seno htiw nageb ehS
”?ffats ruoy no enoemos ro tsinoloc a htiw teem uoy nehw ,taht ekil desserd uoy dniheb gniliart em enigami uoy naC
rehtael der delio eht fo tnecs eht htiw denibmoc hcihw ,taews a pu krow ot gninnigeb saw ilA taht
,yksuh gniworg eciov reh
.nialpxe ot nageb ilA
,liat nwo reh fo pit eht debbarg ehS
”,oN“ .hctorc s'ilA ot
,deretne ehs sa yas ot nageb illaS
”?niaga tuo pils tsuj yeht
t'noW“ .snoitseuq reh fo lla htiw hsiloof ylthgils gnileef
.tsehc dna hcamots reh dnuora ylthgit flesti degguns tius ydob eht sa
,ecnatculer htiw dils tI
”?netfo erom ti raew uoy t'ndid yhw oS“
,emarf lufrewop tub
.ti tuoba thguoht illaS taht won tiusecaps a ekil osla
.der nrut srae reh evah ot nrut reh yltnerappa saw tI
.moc.nozamA
ta seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,ti hguorht gninnur sniev gnilooc sah gninil roiretni ehT“
.ylthgil rood eht no dekconk illaS
yltcaxe saw taht fo noisiv a yllautcA
,elbatrofmoc saw I taht tnatropmi erom
,dias illaS ”,ees I“
.tuoba gnikniht saw illaS tahw
rellirht if-ics eht fo retirw
,daeh reh revo arb strops reh dellup ilA .swap etihw dna
dewolf selcsum lufrewop sti sa reh htaenrednu tsaeb eht fo leef eht
.yletaciled gniffins
,ilA“ .edisni morf deilper ilA
,ruf reh rednu denifed selcsum ygnar ,osrot ehtil reh gnilaever
”,tnemom a ni uoy wohS“
.taorht reh deraelc illaS ”…uoy did woH“
”.hguoht reh ksa dluoc uoY
derediorbme saw daeh s’nexiv gnilrans a fo eliforp ehT
,spiz fo rebmun elbakramer a derutaef dna
,triks reh emac tsriF
deniarts ylthgils gnikool noisserpxe reh ,dias ilA
,einaleM ot meht detnaw ehs yhw nialpxe ot evah d’ehs ,gniht eno roF
,tsaerb thgir eht revo
.sgel reh pu ti gnillup nigeb ot nwod gninael dna tiusydob eht fo dloh gnikat
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ti eveileb nac uoy fi ma I sa trohs sa ,elamef namuh eiddom siht s'erehT
”?elbatrofmocnu taht t'nsI“
”.edistuo eht no ralloc dlo ym fo sniahc eht raew dluoc I os ,taorht ym dnuora thgit tif ot desoppus s'tI“
,tsiaw reh dnuora ti depparts dna tleb tnempiuqe reh debbarg ehS .dias ilA
”.reisae tol a si refsnart taeh eht muucav a ni nrow eb ot tnaem t'nsi ti ecnis ylno
.dne s'reppiz eht yawa gnilaes
,tsehc reh pu tnew xis fo seires a nehT
.ylesool otni tif sdne parts eht taht
”.edamdnah lla ,em rof rehtegot ti tup
.ereh esu hcum eb d’ti ekil ton s’tI“ .deggurhs ilA
....fo egalbmessa elbakramer
.tiag sti rednu dessap dnuorg eht dna
,evals drow eht no kcab tib ylbisiv nexiv regnuoy ehT
,nihc s'ilA tsniaga gnisserp ralloc hgih eht
,tiusydob a morf emac llems rehtael delio ehT
.dias ilA ”,selkcub eht woN“
a saw hcneb eht nO
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.gninil eht hguorht dedaerht sniev dekool tsomla taht
,deilper illaS ”,ees I“ .dias ehs
”?cilbup ni ,taht raew uoy edam ehS“ ”.sreh saw I nehW“
ekil dekool tahw htiw denil roiretni eht
.anosrep nexiV deR
.reh dnoyeb yletelpmoc saw eciffo s'ilA morf gnimoc saw ti yhW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.emit
,dap regnif eno htiw tius eht fo tnorf eht ekorts ot tuo gnihcaer
latem denekcalb fo stols talf tsuj
”,elbuort on s’ti fI“ .deksa ehs
”,em ot siht tnes tsuj einaleM ydaL ,hA“ .noitcurtsnoc sti ni stleb dna selkcub
.deksa illaS ”?gninoitidnoc ria eht pu nrut I dluohS“
.draugydob reh sa reh deinapmocca I nehw evisserpmi kool ot desoppus saw I taht saw aedi ehT“
.tius eht fo tuo ilA tel ehS
.detcejorp ehs ytuaeb eht fo suoicsnocnu
,triks reh fo tekcop a otni etomer eht gnippils ,delims ehS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.sdap reh derevoc yllaitrap taht sparts ssorc fo riap a ni dedne htob tius eht fo sgel ehT
.hgih dleh daeh reh htiw dnats ot reh gnicrof
,ecnecifingam citelhta reh lla ni illaS erofeb erab nexiv gnuoy eht gnivael
reppiz eht fo htgnel eht nwod sregnif reh nur ot egru neddus yrev a gnithgif ,deireuq illaS
hcnebkrow eht tsniaga
.taht ot yas dluoc illaS lla saw ”,hA“
.stros fo mrofinu a saw ti desoppus illaS ,llew
,sgnir purrits eht gnihctulc seot reh
,taorht reh revo eno ta gnidne
,reppiz elbuod a debbarg dna
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.ylevissessop delworg ehs sa
rood eciffo eht dekcol ilA elihw taes s’hcnebkrow eht koot illaS
.noisufnoc yna ni naht
?ti ni kool uoy did woH“
”?ti htiw od ot gniog uoy era tahW“
.erac erom ylbaredisnoc htiw
,seitnap dna sgniggel kcalb reh fo tuo deleep ehs yllanif nehT
”,ydaliM ,eruS“ ”?ni emoc I yam ,ilA“
,suoivbo saw ti metsys gnilooc s'tius eht etipseD
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
tnurg trohs a tuo tel ilA sa gnihctaw ,os did illaS
.deggurhs ehS .dias ilA
.tnemssarrabme htiw der gniworg srae
.rebmemer I taht serutcip oN“
.dias ilA ”,thgif a ni stnemevom ym edepmi tub pleh t'nac rehtael eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tuons reh tsniaga regnif reh gnippat ,dias ehs
.gnitcartsid ylgnisaercni gniworg saw
”,mrH“ .sesserd ym hctam ot ,eulb ni emac ylno ti fi woN
,stif gniht siht sa thgit sA“
,palf etarapes a htiw reppiz eht gnirevoc
tcapmoc s'ilA ot dettif motsuc ylsuoivbo ;llams saw tI .der doolb
.deerga ilA ”,boj doog a did
.tius suolevram reh dna ilA fo tnecs denibmoc eht ni gnikat
.pu gnidir morf tius eht peek pleh ot tnaem ylsuoivbo
”.os kniht t’nod I“
,ylluferac gnihtaerb ,dias ilA
. yaD ecyoR yb serutnevdA nexiV deR ehT dna ,srotisiV ehT
”,noitpo tseb taht si odnammoc gniog
”,selkcub eht dna rehtael eht ni deddebme stengam gnisu ,sparts tramS“
,ruf fo tsen rieht ni elbisiv selppin reh gnivael
,trihs reh rednu neddih yllamron
”...reh saw I nehw kcab em rof edam ehs mrofinu a s'tI“
,eugnot yna gnikcal
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,deksa illaS ”?krow taht seod woH“
”.ti sserP“ .dekramnu
.sehtolc reh fo tuo gnippirts neht
.esuolb reh gninottubnu erofeb edisa gnittes dna ti gnidlof
.illaS ot ti gnidnah
,ffo nekat saw taht nehT
.snopaew reh dednet yllamron ehs erehw
.eson reh ot liat reh fo esab eht morf pu revihs a gnidnes
”.egarots otni ti tup sseug I“
suoregnad erom hcum eht neht dna
”.sllabhtom otni walC eht tup ehs retfa raeg ym fo tser eht htiw kcab ti tnes ehS
”,eruS“ .ti saw taht ,ria eht ni ninnat fo tnecs eht neeb evah tsum tI
.dias ilA ”,ydalim ,oN“
.rehtael delio fo llems eht ssim t'ndluoc uoY yaD ecyoR yb
.sgniggel reh gnivael
,eson s'illaS ot suoivbo yrev
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.edis eno ot tes dap gnibbur a dna elttob a fo ecnedive eht yb delio yltnecer
,kcat eht fo kaerc ehT
,kcen reh dnuora thgit ni desolc tius eht litnu
taht ni liob ot gniog uoy t'nerA“
,htuoy reh ni nekat dah ehs sedir fo seiromem kcab thguorb ti dnim s'illaS nI
,ti esol t'ndluow I os ,tuo tnew ew nehw ti otno dloh ot desu einaleM ydaL ....ssertsiM“
.romuh elbanoitseuq rehtar s’wal-ni-retsis reh fo ttub eht gnieb ekil leef t’ndid ehs dna
”?siht tuohtiw esaeler t'nod yeht dnA“
”,semit fo elpuoc a ylnO“ .deksa illaS
,sbuc gnuoy rof elbatius
.etomer eht gniregnif ,deksa illaS
,yaD ecyoR yb ”rehtaeL deliO“