.ti etagivan ot woh hguorht leef ot evah d’eh dna
,reporp etib a gnikat
,saera rewollahs eht fo eno ot revo delddap raeb ehT
.dnarg saw eerT ehT
,flesti dniw eht llems dluoc eH
,ytimertxe eht gnitanimod mlap a morf drawkcab gnipols tsirw eht
,evol peed retsof ot yticapac eht htiw seiceps A
?thgir ,taht ta doog saw ydob sih ,dnik siH
,dniwpu sraeb eht llems dluoc eH
,sworromot nrobnu eht fo raef llitsni
,htron hctac sih deirrac eH
,egdel enots eht no deggel ssorc tas raeb-
,pu deraer eh ylevitatnet tsomlA
,dnuor raey hcum ytterp lufituaeb s’ti ,erus naem I
.emit saw tI  .gnihctaw
,dezeeuqs raeb ehT
,edis sih no ereht yal ykrapS ,seye sih gninepO  .thgir
,sdrawkcab dexaler ykrapS
.roolf tserof eht evoba reyal eht fo ytiralc eht ,ssenhserf
.tey eerT ehT debmilc neve t’ndah eh dna gnizama saw weiv eht
,enil eert eht ta thgir tub
,dellits gnihtaerb sih sA
.mih dedlom raeb eht fo mhtyhr eht
,lios yssom pmad otni knas seot siH
.tserof eht no nwod gnillaf dna sduolc eht gnicreip skaerts egnaro elprup
,revo llef kaidoK ehT
,demaercs tsomla eh
,swap sih gninoitisoper fo dnuor rehtonA  .rednet dna kaew
,ezirp sih ta kool retteb a teg ot nwod denarc raeb ehT .bmocyenoh siht tub ,KO
.kool ti edam susrU sa ysae sa t’nsaw siht KCUF
,gniog saw eh erehw yllareneg wenk eH
.esae htiw ytilitsoh lacitrev eht gnitagivan
.tserof raeb eht fo taeb ehT
,eert eht pu nar tsomla raeb eht ,retsaf dna retsaF
,elggurts a eb ot ti detcepxe d’eh wohemoS
.pu mih fo tser eht gnillup
,ehtaerb ot gnivah
,nalp ydob namuh a nI
,tae ot detrats dna erohs eht fo swollahs eht ot muws eh nomlas eht gniyrraC
.lufituaeb yllaicepse s’ti
.erofeb ,ereh thgir
,siht ta dab os neeb evah sdnah dluoc woh ,parc yloH
ereh pu weiv ehT :yadirF
.ksat laveirter eht fo edis rehto eht no taert eht fo sesimorp htiw meht gnitaoc
.deneppah ti neht dnA
,llems a dah skcor eht nevE .sdrib dna
,tib yb tib ,neht tuB
.pets yreve sih gnitnuah rednimer elbakahsnu na
,evac sih ot kcab
.eugnot sih otno gnippird yenoh teews etsat ydaerla dluoc eH
.nar nomlas eht erehw telni eht raen tserof eht morf gnigreme
.raey txen nomlas erom eb ereht yam - meht ykcul
”raeb ’nieb nO“ saw sihT      .ezirp sih
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ytilibissopmi fo kcirt cigam a ekil tlef dah eert eht pu gniredipS
.mih htaeneb klub ’susrU fo llaf dna esir cimhtyhr eht htiw gnizinorhcnys ylwols htaerb sih
,dnuora devruc ro ,tfel eht ot htap eht nekat evah dluow ykrapS ,erofeb
,ydob siht ni gnizama saw gninnuR
,ecipicerp deggaj eht pu yaw sih kcip ylluferac erom dna nwod mlac
saw eh ereht gniyal
,enuJ-dim ,won tub
,retaw eht morf gnigremE  .saw eh
,xim teews yrovas a ,yenoh dna avraL
.niks sih gnihcaer
:noitarbiv rieht tlef eH
,ylwolS  .devloser saw eH
.tnemom eht ta mih ot yaw taht demees eruS
ykrapS yb ”raeb ’nieb nO“
.sburhs llams gnidneb dna sessarg neewteb gnidils sgel
.swalc ekil-reggad kcalb evif htiw deppit
.ydob sih delttar
,ysae saw eert eht otno gnidloh
.noitamrofsnart enisru sih fo edit sseltneler eht yb demusbus
,ni dellup sgel dna smra s’ykrapS
.yad s’ykrapS fo thgilhgih eht netfo erew tserof raeb eht hguorht sllorts gninroM gnihsiF
,sredluohs sih neewteb esuohrewop a otni gnidnuom selcsum
tlef mrof wen siH
.kcab s’dneirf namuh-flah sih dnuora ylevitcetorp gnilruc
,hgis detnetnoc a evag ykrapS
.edis enisru sih morf detirehni dah eh tiart a saw
,etsat larenim taht
.kcab sih fo llams eht otni nwod dna kcen sih morf pu gnivruc pmuh eht
,noitome erom ,cigol ssel
,pu dekool sraeb lareveS
,gnidaerps ssenpmad eht ,tsrub spord eroM
,yllaudividni dab t’nerew yehT .sgnits erom ,kcuF
.ni lla ti gnikat
.derrits ykrapS ,owt ebyam
,elbmert senob ruoy
.drah yrt ot evah ot
,ydaets emaceb gnihtaerb s’raeb eht
.gninnuts saw weiv ehT
.ydob sih gnikcarw mhtyhr eht
.ti tuoba gnihtyreve gnillems
,esir nus eht gnihctaw ,tas ykrapS
.mih fo edis rehtie ot pu gnitluav dna ,raeb eht gnihctac retaw
.esnopser a tcepxe t’ndid eH
,dnuoforp erom ,rewol
…eht rewoprevo t’ndluoc enip tnegnup eht neve
.rehtegotla gniht tnereffid yleritne na si noitca
.enips sih otni raeppasid
,ytilibats gnirevawnu eht ,rewop war eht
sgniht hcus rof derac sraeb taht toN
.teef sih no doog tlef maol eht
,dnuorg eht ot flesmih derewol raeb ehT
,deef ot ydob lufrewop a
.gninetrohs sregnif sih
.retaw eht hguorht mih dniheb gniliart sgel kcab
,mih dellif raeb eht fo enot nehtrae peed ehT .deirruh ssel
,’akerue‘ gnituohs pu pmuj t’ndid eh
?woN .ecnatsid a morf
,remmus fo yzal eht yb derepmet ylerab won gnirps ni efil fo ycnegru ehT
,KO  .os ylbaeciton
,dah dlo sih ecnatsiser eht reffo t’ndid mrof wen siH .mih saw
,gninrom taht snoitalever eseht fo eno dah ykrapS
,ti edam nomlas eht fo tsoM
,secalp ffo raf morf seirots gniyrrac tsug hcae
.htgnerts sih ot yaw evag xaw eht sa smug sih
.bmuht desoppo taht
,yltbus dengilaer sgel dna sredluohS
.sdniw eht morf detalumucca dah hcihw lios ymaol stekcop ynit eht ot tnematset
raw ni sdrows dedleiw osla
,retaw fo sllems llits dnuorg ehT
.deklaw ykrapS ,s’gninrom sih rof lamron saw sA
,denedaorb lluks siH
.dnuorg delbbep eht no ereht yal raeb A .deppots neht
,htdiw ni denedaorb eh
.egdel gnippan etirovaf sih ot kcab
.hcaeb eht otno despalloc raeb eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ylthgils detsiwt ykrapS
?level eye s’raeb ta thgir
,niatnuoM raeB fo weiv gnikathtaerb eht htiw gnola
.tserof eht htiw gnimihc
elbmarcs a saw gnihtyrevE
.erac ot demees meht fo enon tub ,tuoba demrala
,wols yllanif did raeb eht ,htaerb fo tuO
.htgnerts nwo sih fo erusnu tsomla deyaws raeb ehT  .mih saw sihT
,neerg dna yffulf saw ssom ehT
.sdoow eht hguorht devom eh sa thgir os tlef reven dah ykrapS
.lla ta erofeb gnihtyna dellems reven d’eh ekil tlef eh
,noitroporp sti ni toof edargitnalp a won
”.tol a uoy tuoba kniht I“  :desum ykrapS
.enots eht ssorca rac llams a fo thgiew eht detaolf taht noitazinorhcnys diuqil ni gnicnad sbmil evissam eht
,emit a ta wolb ecreif eno latem gnipahs htimskcalb enisru na ekiL
,pot eht gnitserC
,siht ekil elttil a tlef ykrapS
.ria s’remmus mraw fo ytilativ eht
.ecnedac gnitser a otni gnilttes
.noitarbiv sti fo noitaitnatsni gnivil a
,egde sdnop eht ot gnilrufnu sgel
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
flah cihpromoporhtna eht ykrapS
,hguor tlef krab ehT
.dluoc reven sdnah erem ekil retaw eht ni noitcart gnidnif swap evissam ,maws ykrapS
.gnillif ylleb sih ,siht fo derit eh yllautnevE
.evih eht ot pu thgiarts gniklaw raeb eht
,mih delggob sllems fo dlrow wen sihT
.dnop eht fo ecafrus eht gnikaerb hsif a fo hsalps eht dna
,lufrednow tlef dnuorg pmadwed eht revo edirts yrevE
,ysae gnidnats edam nalp ydob nwo siH
.raeb eht fo ytilibats ykcots eht tlef
,tserof eht morf ni deddolp susrU sa derrits ylerab eH
,tnecsa deredluob eht pu dekool eH
,yrolg sti lla ni ekaL raeB
,ekahs sgnul ruoY
.taeb yb taeb gninekciht
:yadsruhT ffuts raeb ’niod fo eugolipE  .tnetnoc
,niar ecin a saw tI
.revoc poteert eht hguorht gnittuc thgilgninrom fo smaeb ytsim eht hguorht mih gnilleporp ydob sih ssorca noitazinorhcnys lanogaid ,rehtegot dexelf spih dna sredluohs siH
,dehtaerb raeb ehT
.neerg eht thguorb ti ,efil saw ti
.flesmih pleh t’ndluoc eh
.emit siht retsaf
,won mih hguorht dewolf ti eroM .lla ta ton
- ’sruoh‘ ,’setunim‘ ,’sdnoces‘
.ylthgit deppirg won eh eno yppas eht tub seert rif eht lla llew
,ria eht hguorht detfaw seldeen enip fo llems ehT
,ereh pu ria erup eht llems dluoc eH
.cigam enisru fo elknirps
,erac t’ndid ykrapS
.tsap sih fo thguoht ykrapS
,slirtson sih ni kciht saw yenoh fo llems eht ,secap raeb ytnewt morf nevE
,elzzum sih derewol eh ,derretednU
.remmah neesnu eht fo swolb gnitnelernu eht rednu
.raeb eht fo refoowbus eht no gnittis saw eh ekil
,yllausU  .eerT ehT ,ni deltsen saw evac sih edasilap etinarg eht fo pot no gniworg eert enip dlo gib a ,hguoht dnim ni eno dah eH .sedivorp tserof eht :sdeen raeb eht sgniht lla htiw sa
,deppolf ykrapS ,ecnart sih nI
,sregnif sih nwod derettacs sehctap denedrah yllauqe ,rellams htiw
?erofeb siht fo yna deciton ton eh dah woh
.lellarap enisru sih
.ydob sih hguorht gniwolf raeb eht ot ytinamuh fo ecnelubrut eht dda t’ndid
,lios ykcor eht no gnithgila yltneg sdaptoof yrehtaeL .yllufthguoht
.htped yldlrowrehto na tserof eht evag seldeen enip no spordniar fo rettap tfos eht dna
,retawrednu dlrow eht fo dnuos detrotsid ehT
?thgir ,ysae dekool tI
.pmuj lanif eht devarb hsif eht eno yb enO
.stsim gninrom ylrae eht hguorht gnillaf stelpord ynit fo seirrulf
,mih ekat ti tel eH
:yadnoM raeb a gnimoceb nO  ykrapS yb
.sgnidnuorrus eneres eht ni gnikaos
.seeb fo tol a saw taht TSIRHC -no desucof saw ykrapS
,emarf hsulp s’raeb eht otni gnixaler ,dehgis ykrapS
,ssentew dloc eht gnileef ,retaw eht otnI
,flesmih ot thguoht eh dab os t’nsaw tahT
stnemeveihca gnikathtaerb dna stluaf gniralg sti lla htiw
.nruter ni gnizilacov
.ecaf sih ta dorp ot kcor eht no bmocyenoh eht deppord eH
,ria eht ni gnuh retaw fo llems eht
.eugnot sih tuohtiw tub
,ssentew emaceb ssenpmad nehT
,ybraen tserof eht fo enil eert eht evoba saw gnipporctuo ehT
,sselthgiew os leef t’ndluohs gib siht gnihtemoS
,tseroF raeB eht ni ysae ytterp si eert elbatius a gnikcip woN
.nodnaba tnedifnoc htiw sehcnarb eht hguorht pu gnivaew dna krab eht gnippirg won swap
,sraeb eht dna tserof eht hguorht yaw sti sevaew tI
.eavral yrettub eht fo spop ytsrub dna
,gnitiaw tneitap ehT
.kcab dna yknip sih ot xedni sih morf gnitaludnu evaw a
.pitwalc kcalb hcae ot htap a gnikram
.eton tnegnup ,teews rieht gnidda krab srehctarcs kcabffurcs eht
,gniht eno era snoisiceD
.efil sih fo thgilhgih a ekil tlef klaw s’yadoT
.thgiew sih gnibrosba
.remmus fo taeh gniretsilb eht htiw epacsdnal eht raes ot tey sah nus ehT
.ecalp eht htiw cnys otni emac ykrapS
,sllaf eht fo pil eht no tser ot gnimoc swaperof
,citamard erom emaceb segnahc ehT
,niaga dehctiwt yeht taeb evissergorp hcae htiW
,mlap eht ta dekool eh wap sih gninruT .bmuht elbasoppo
,regnuoy saw eh nehW
,tserof eht fo trap saw niar ehT
.raeb a saw ykrapS
:dneirf sih deivne eh ,oot sihT
,ti ekam t’ndid ralucitrap ni nomlas eht fo enO
,daeh ’susrU gnikorts yltneg llits wap thgir siH  ”.era uoy yaw ehT
,meht ot laiceps t’nsaw cigam hcuS
.erehwyreve ,ycnarbiv taht
.raeb eht fo taeb gnidduht yreve gnileef
.ssenecreif enotirab eht ,ti fo ezis ehT
,meht revocsid sa hcum os snoisiced ekam t’nod uoy semitemoS  .’gnivresednu‘
.yenoh eht tuoba saw seviheeb dna sraeb thguoht syawla d’eh
,ekal raeb tlems reveN
.erofeb deciton reven dah raeb eht yaw a ni ria eht ni gnuh llits oga syad wef a fo niar ehT
.llaf s’wap hcae morf gnidolpxe selbbep fo yarps a ,erohs eht nwod gnidduht raeb fo sdnuop 006 ,nar ykrapS ,gnidnuob woN .rehtona neht
,denruhc meht fo smraws evisulli
,enips enisru eht gnola hcterts ot pal sih morf gnisir smra
.detsuahxe saw ykrapS
.gnipporctuo eht morf tsgnoma tuo dekool ykrapS yponac eht naht rehgih gnidnats pot sti
.hsif rof gnilgna
,ydob nwo sih ni htoB
,detrotnoc kcab s’ykrapS
.daD regdaB yldduC a ,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,ykrapS yb
.neesnu nehw neve dedeeh
.eert eht gnigguh sredluohs lufrewop
.dnuora maws eh ,decnad eh ,decnarp eH
,lios ymaol eht htiw gnitcennoc swap talf egral
,dehctiwt swap sih tsriF
.orf dna ot trad seilfnogard eht dehctaw
.gnitnap ,deppots ykrapS
,tnemom raeb a retfA  .gnihtyreve
.erofeb siht ekil dlrow eht dellems reven d’eH  .gnihtaerb
,ylwolS .erom dehctiwt
,rehtona neht dna
,rehtona ot krof gninut eno fo noitarbiv citehtapmys eht ekiL
.dnop eht ni daeh sih deppid ykrapS
.gninrom eht llems dluoc ykrapS
.oot leef mih pleh dluow tserof raeb eht hguorht klaw a ebyam dna
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
,erohs nrehtuos eht yb nwod saw eH  .ekal raeb ot
.depoh d’eh naht rellams saw tI
.ekaw sti ni tfel ssenhserf
.dnatsrednu dna eviecrep ylneddus dluoc eh seirots
.dnim s’raeb-flah eht ni decnad
.sraeb tuoba setirw yllanoisacco tub ,tenretni eht ta dab yllaer s’ohw
.werg mih fo trap yreve
,ylluferac dehcaorppa eH
,siht ekil t’ndid yllareneg snamuH
,sregnif derruf-nworb sih neht ,ti gnilggiw ,tuo dna ni bmuht sih devom ykrapS
.detrap retaw eht woh yb dezama ,evod eH
.erom owT  .gnits rehtonA
,mih koohs ,mih devom tI
,sgnits eht erongi ot tseb sih gnioD
,srekaeps eht fo tnorf ni thgir doots dna trecnoc a ot enog reve uoy evaH
,redluohs evissam-won sih otni brosba thgiew eht tlef eH
.tohs a ti evig d’eh derugif ykrapS
.no detser eh redluohs evissam eht ta gnizag
.enif tsuj gnola tog dna htob dekcal susrU
,deirav stluseR
.mih dekcohs tsehc sih morf detpure taht ’kkkkkkkkkkkgnnnnnyyyh‘ ehT .tuo dellac ykrapS ,yldeticxE
.egnahc etamilc fo smsinahcem eht dereenigne dna
.nar ykrapS ,htuom ni ezirP
.stnemele eht ni ,dekan ,tew gnieb
,daeh ’susrU fo rufeltsirb ylio ,esraoc eht hguorht gnilffur wap thgir sih fo sregnif eht
”raeb ’nieb nO“   yojne esaelP
.tserof eht fo sliart nrow ressel eht gnola gnirednaem ,suotiucric saw klaw siH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ytinamuh sih fo skramrae modnar eht fo eno emoceb dah ssenllat eht
,og tel waperof thgir siH .laivirt
.tiusrup lairea eht tsol osla eh yllautneve dna
,tsrub telpord eno tsriF .t’ndid yeht
,pmuts eht ot deppets eh sa pil sih gnits eno tlef ykrapS
.elbignatni ,elbisivni
.lufrednow tlef siht dna
,demees ti ,tnemtnetnoC
,dedisbus ro degnahc raeb eht fo taeb eht taht toN
?thgir ,seeb eht morf noitativni na yllacitcarP
.yoj fo htrow ytrap yadhtrib sdik a ,sllirht fo edir lavinrac a
,erofeb susrU otni detcejorp d’eH
.kcen dna ,ecaf ,smug ,spil sih ni deddebme sregnits fo snezod leef osla dluoc eH
.noitisoppo rieht gnisol ,sregnif htiw tnemngila otni deppans sbmuhT
,siht ekil si raeb eht fo taeb ehT
.lufituaeb tlef eciov siH
.sselehtreven retaw eht detpecca yeht tub
.esruoc fo ,ti deirt d’eH
,meht tsgnoma gniyaL
.did yeht ekil flesmih gnineerp
,nus eht fo noissapmoc eht htiw gnillif sgnul
.gnihton did osla sihT
rehto hcae htiw kcol ot hguone gnol regnol on sevlac
,niar eht hguorht deklaw ykrapS
.niar eht ni gniklaw
.won saw ti suoivbo os ,ton evah eh dluoc woH
.draeh eb ot dedeen
,yltcerid os siht dootsrednu sraeb eht detbuod eh esruoc fO
,wap thgir sih htiw nwod hsif eht gnidloh
,yawa decaf mlap ,ti ta dekool eH
.eciton t’ndid eh
.tserof eht saw sa ,saw tsuj ti
.ycnegru fo esnes detarogivni na tlef raeb eht tub
,smaebnus no tuoba detaolf llits seeb detsudnellop ,demoolb llits srewolF
,knurt eht ot gnignilc flah
,degnahc oot ydob siH
.saw eh naht erom tib a yrruh susrU nees syawla d’eh ,etal oot tnemom a dezilaer ykrapS
.desum eh ,ekil tlef taog niatnuom eht tahw siht saW
,pil sih fo edisni eht gnignits seeb ,eerf ti dellup eH
,cisum eht emoceb uoy
.osrot sih fo tnorf ni ,nwod detniop sbmil sih
,rehtona neht dna ,pets a koot eH
:gnikniht fo yaw tnereffid a ot dnuora emoc d’eh ,hguoht tserof raeb eht dnuof d’eh ecnO
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,kniht mih depleh gniklaW
,noitucexe tsenif eht fo polf ylleb a saw gnidnal ehT
.pal sih ni dleh ylesool
.saw eh yrgnuh woh dezilaer ykrapS ,ekaL raeB fo htuos tsuj sllaf revir eht ot gnimoC
,regae oot yas neve thgim srevresbo edistuO
,htgnel ni dehcterts eH
,ereht thgir evih a gnittuP
.erutan ot mhtyhr niatrec a s’erehT
,elkcunk driht eht ot detarapes sregnif :mrof ni tsael ta
.gnihton did hself yrgna eht revo ti gnidils ,wap a gnitfiL
.mih egnahc ot detrats ti ,taeb tahT
.taert a ytsat sa tsuj erew eavral eeb eht :kcab sraey terces eht no ni mih tel dah susrU
.revihs ro hsiuqs regnol on sdaptoof tub
.leef uoy gnihtemos s’ti ,raeh uoy
,siht ekil sgninrom no tub
,wap tnorf s’raeb eht ta nwod dekool neht
.erusaem ekat ot evac railimaf sih ta pots a ot gnimoc
,deirrac eh bmoc eht morf seeb eht egdolsid did swap sih fo noitarbiv gnidnuop ehT
,riaffa yrgnuh a saw raeb a gnieB
,tuoba suoiruc eb thgim sraeb gniht fo dnik eht ekil demees ekal eht fo edis eht no gnisluvnoc mrof hsiraeb-ylgnisaercni eht fo thgis ehT
?nalp ydob raeb eht nI .elbmarcs a neeb evah dluow siht
,sraeb fo yaw eht saw hcuS
,doog tlef syawla ti tub
.dne no dnats riah sih gnileef ,delgnit eH
;mrof evissam ylwen sih demraw nus ehT
,tsen eht otni dehcaer eH
,namuh naht raeb erom raf dekool ytimertxe sih nooS
.teg ot eliga oot dna ,hcaer ysae fo tuo
,ton dna elzzird a neewteb erehwemos
.evom uoy yaw ehT“
,dnuorg delbbep eht no deggel-ssorc gnitser
,ytinamuh fo segamI
,sgel sih tsniaga dehsurb snreF
.sgel sih yb emit a ta eno dewollof ,tfel sih nehT
,desare yllaudarg erew stiart namuh sih fo segitsev ehT
,ereht ro ereh gnivil a tuo gnike noitategev fo stib llams htiw kcor fo selip
,ydob sih hguorht depmup doolb ehT
.gnieb sih fo rebif yreve gnitaemrep tnemeticxe citenerf
.riah tsudtirg esraoc sih ot elttab eht gnisol noisnet ecafrus
,raeB eht fo yellaV eht dnuora gnippuc
yenoh yeoog ni gnitaolf seceip yxaw kciht eht
.htuom sih htiw hself gniraet
,tserof eht evoba llih eht no gniworg
.weiv fo dleif sih otni dna
,revir eht hguorht daerps
:snoitcidartnoc krats yb dekram seiceps a saw tI
,ytivarg fo llup sseltneler eht gniyfed
,ria eht ni gniylf seeb eroM
sehcti yranigami gnisaet spit walc
yrteop thguorwdrow dna seinohpmys detfarc taht sdnah emas eht
.sbmoc yxaw nworbegnaro eht morf dna ot emac yeht sa cigam yb fi sa dednepsus
llems dluoc eH .tserof eht
,detarbiv dirbyh eht nihtiw peed gnihtemos
,hsalf a sa emoc t’ndid tI
.tnereffid saw siht ,hguoht sihT
.ezirp sih htiw tserof eht hguorht dednuop eh sa sniev s’raeb eht hguorht desruoc enilanerda eruP
,sregnif detarapes esoht morf tog eh tahw tuoba thguoht eH
,thguac dna ,nwod deppolf eh emit tsal enO
,reporp ekal eht otni gnigrahC
tub sdaPi no epyt ro eeffoc ekam t’ndid raeb eht ,eruS
.nwonknu ylsuoiverp hturt peed emos gnizilaer fo tnemom ah-ha eht
,mih dnuora sraeb eht tlef eH
,ylbakatsimnu tub
,serutxet fo egnalem a
,rehgih dehcaer sniatnuom eht ,eruS
.eert a gnibmilc yrt ot dedeen eh taht thgin tsal thgin ta etal dezilaer dah ykrapS
.syaw namuh erom ni snamuh eht htiw gnitcaretni ,sgel owt no gniklaw
,dap kcalb derutxet kciht a
,erohs eht yb tas dirbyh ehT
settengiv emos erahs ot ekil d’eH
.kcans gnilggirw eht otni gniknis hteet
.woN fo ytilaer eht morf edisa stcurtsnoc namuh lla
;nirg tseggib eht otni nepo dekcarc wam s’ykrapS
seert enip eht hguorht gnosdrib gniltsur dniw eht fo seidolem eht yb detautcnup saw enecs eht fo ssenllits ehT
:taht naht renialp saw ti
,ecneserp erem sih yb tespu oot t’nerew s’eeb eht ,eruS
.ti morf gniog dna gnimoc revir eht
.raey fo emit siht lufituaeb si tserof raeb ehT
.yaw evig sllec yxaw eht gnileef
?snib ssab eht fo tnorf ni thgir
.gnola lla mih fo tnorf ni ereht thgir saw tahw fo ecnatpecca dna ssenerawa laudarg a tsuj erom
,htap siht otno yaw sih tlef d’eH
,taeb yb taeb denehtgnel mlap lapracatem eht
.detiaw eh ,retaw htped-ylleb ni gnidnats woN
,htuom dehctertstuo sih otni gnivid tub lla hsif a fo barg riadim ysae na htiw ffo gniyap ecneitap sraeb eht
,noitcafsitassid railucep fo esnes a htiw ykrapS dellif dah edirts ladepib sih ot nruter yrevE .thgir …tlef
.htgnel koot ti erehw htrig dedda opmet eht sa gninetrohs
.meht tuoba etorw eh
,oot yaw siht kniht ot desu ykrapS
.ruf nworb kciht sih ffo nar dna pu dedaeb tsrif stelporD
.yluJ fo taeh eht ffo evats ot ecnalabretnuoc deen syad enuJ mraW
.ssenippah knip thgirb neht dna
.tespu elttil a erew yeht ebyam
,dewols segnahc eseht ,yllautnevE
:egnahc ot detrats yeht
.yojelgnit otni meht gnidderhs yllufyalp neht
.od yeht sa gnihsif
.eert eht no rehgih toof a gninoitisoper
,ereh deklaw dah taht sraeb eht llems dluoc eH
.nugeb tsuj dah ,saw ti sa wols
,niks rekciht eht htiW
.dnuorg ykcor semitemos ,nevenu ot ni gniknis sdaptoof
fo noiton eht eviecnoc dna
.selbbep eht deffins reven
…erofeb sevih diar sraeb dehctaw d’eh ,eruS
,eert eht ta gnippirg
.ti revo dehcterts niks s'raeb a htiw dnah namuh A
,drawrof pets a koot eH
,knurt eht etadommocca ot gnidaerps swaperof ,pu emarf sih gnillup spih
.ytinamuh fo thguoht eH
taebmurd ehT :yadsendeW
.saw tsuj retaw dna yllis erew sehtolc
,yadoT .llih eht pu gnidnew
raey fo emit sihT
;sgniht yas ot dedeen tsuj ykrapS ,semitemoS
,ezeerb eht ni yltneg elppir dnop eht dehctaw eH
,hcnarb a no tas-flaH
,hsif ,srewolf ,sraeb eht ,enip eht ,ssom ehT
.laog laer sih saw yenruoj eht
.egnops dekaosesaerg a taoc s’raeb-flah eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.pot eht morf pael sih gnirewop sgel raer ,mih fo tnorf ni deyalps sgelerof ,tsrifdaeh sllaf eht revo evod ykrapS
.egdel ykcor eht no detalp
,kaidoK lacipyt eht naht rellams elttil a saw raeb siht ebyaM
,namuh yrev saw wap s’dirbyh ehT
,pmuts eert eht ni
,ereh pu morf erutxet ekipstsorf tnadrev a tub erew seert rif ehT
,ecalp fo tuo tsomla demees rewot depparw-krab ehT
,taebtraeh s’ykrapS did os
.ecnatsid eht ni sraeB fo yellaV eht dna
,enog saw yadretsey fo niar ehT
.gnibmilc eert rof saw gninrom sihT
,dnuorg eht tsniaga talf smlap tlef
.kcor demraw-nus eht no delwarps ydob dekan
.dnuorg delbbep eht otno mlap thgir tnorf sih fo leeh eht gnirewol
,sehtolc gniraew ,oga gnol
,detrotnoc sbmil sih pmuht ecreif hcae htiW
.ykrapS rof degnahc taeb ehT
.nihtiw morf tuo flesti gnitserw mrof wen a
,htrae eht llems dluoc eH
,dnoces a ecno gnitaeb ylerab tsrif
.esacriats a erew ti fi sa ylisae sa esir hgih ydoow eht gnisrevart ,rehtona dnA
,)retaw fo etsat eht tub thguan otno hteet fo gnippans eht
.yenoh htiw taf worg ot gnitrats erew sevih wodaem eht
.sgniht hcus ot dnopser ot sraeb fo yaw eht t’nsaw tI
,pot eht raen saw eh gnizilaeR
.sdap wap sih ot yppirg dna tcnitsid erutxet yggarc a
.semit wef a elcyc siht detaeper eH
.sih otni detcejorp mih detadommocca dna dnik neeb dah susrU nehw semit wef a dna
tsieh eviH :yadrutaS
.ti dnuora pirg ot
.ekal eht ot teg ot pu emoc ot dah yeht ,enif saw tahT
,daeh s’tserkcab dnuofwen sih ta kool ot gninrut daeh siH
.sbmoc eht fo eno dnuora gnisolc hteet
.ecnats deggel-ssorc lamron sih ni
,god.ecioveht ta
,ydaerla ereht erew sraeb nezod A
;ria hguorht gnitaolf seirots neddih fo esrevinu a
spop larecsiv ,euqsetorg htiw gnignarraer enips dna kcen sih ,kcab gnulf saw daeh s’ykrapS ,edis sih no yal eh sA
,sniatnuom eht revo gnisir nus ehT
:od ereh shtap tsom erehw mih del htap eht ,yllautnevE
,gel raer a detfil eH
.niks sih ssorca daerps rufeltsirb esraoc elihw
,doots eh emit siht
,tserof eht fo gnos ehT
”,KKKKKKKKKKKKKKKKk kkkkk hhhhH nnnnnnnnYYYYYHHHHHH“    .yks eht dna aes eht dna stnalp dna hsif fo dellems retaw eht ,dog yM
.denekciht kcen sih sa gnihprom dna gnitrotsid serutaef sih
.mih fo erawa saw ylniatrec evih eht tub
.llits yltneuqerf ssel neht
.dedivorp sgel ruof lla no gniklaw dnuorg eht htiw noitcennoc etamitni eht
,sraeb eht tsgnoma sklaw gninrom fo nosaes retfa nosaes nI
.niar yb dekcehc saw htmraw taht gninrom sihT
,tnecs retawhserf eht
,woleb dlrow eht denwo nomlaS
.htgnerts rof deppirts ytilaudividni rieht ,gninioj sregnif
,semit wef a flesmih tohsrevo tsomla eh esae hcum os htiw mih detfil spih dna sredluohs siH
.yoj reehs fo tuo emit siht ,niaga detnurg eH
,mrof sih deddap taF
gnihtemos ton s’tI ?ydob ruoy gnilttar dnuos fo sttaw 000,01
netfo ,ko ,semitemos ro( hctac eht
.lios ymaol eht no sdaptoof sih fo llirht eht no desucof yrev t’nsaw ykrapS tub
.edih sih ni kcirp erem a
.mih ekat ti gnittel
.tsud fo etsat tsrif ehT
,ria eht ni tfirda erew seeB
.dnuorg delbbep eht no gnignahc ydob
.daD regdaB yldduC a
kcab s’raeb eht morf wap tfel sih gnitfil
.bmilc ot mih devom raeb eht fo tirips eht
.flesmih rof emos erocs ot regae saw ykrapS
.swap deppirgeert no thgiew s’raeb eht gnitroppus ylluf won
.gnitae erew yeht nomlas eht llems
.no tas dirbyh eht kcor eht gnilbmert spets evissam sih fo eno yreve
.flesti tserof eht sa dlo ,eert rif dlo gnisopmi na si eerT ehT
,sgel htiw egdirf a rof ecarg lacixodarap a htiw devom susrU
,rednaw ot ezag sih dewolla ykrapS
.etsat ot setsat ynam os ,erots ot taf
?yllaer ,sgniht esoht erew tnatropmi woh
deyojne raeb eht
,rehto eht detfil neht dna
.mrof sih otni deremmah rehtona retfa noitamrofed citsalp ynit enO
yad yniar A :yadseuT
.worram sih hguorht gnitarebrever
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ecafrus s'retaw eht htaeneb dlrow eht fo ytilaernu ykrum hsieulb taht
.pirg ot gnilruc ,segde ykcor dnuora depparw swap gnortS
.sruof lla ot flesmih gnithgir ylwols ,doots eH
,desuf selkcunk owt neewteb hself eht dna ,taeb rehtonA
,retaw eht ni ereh tey dna
,gninthgil fo ekirts citamard on
,elbisiv saw ekaL raeB fo keep ynit a
,dertah sselesab rof snosaer tnevni tey
.tegrat sih otno nwod dna mir eht revo gnireep