.tsal t’nod yeht tub ,selbbauqs dna staps ruo evah ew ,eruS
.gnihtabnus ro gnipeels erew yad eht fo trap tsettoh eht gnirud doirep tser rieht evah ot hguone ykcul seno ehT
.sretsnom rof tresed eht peews dna ,su fo tol elohw eht
.yresrun eht ni nerdlihc eht gnidnim emos
.rettiwT no reetyksuH@ sa ro
boj eht htiw no teg ot detnaw ohw su fo esoht neewteb nageb stnemugrA
,esruoc fo ,emoc ot sdik eht dednetni su fo enoN
,xelpmoc dnuorgrednu eht fo retlehs eht rof delbmarcs eW
.elggurts a fo ngis on
.ecnef eht ni tuc d’yeht tniop tixe eht ta gnitiaw yrtnes desumanu na dnuof yeht erehw
.dniheb raf ton erew su fo tser eht tub
.neris eht draeh t’ndah tsuj gnissim eht dna
,dilos naht ssel gnihtemos ot eson tfos a dehcuot su fo enO
.ffo tnew mrala eht nehw tniop tsehgih rieht ta erew snus ehT   reetyksuH yb
,)eci dna taem fo dellems ti(
gnihtemos ees ton dluoc ,sevlesruo ,ew esuaceb tsuJ
.ni deggat dah ohw fo kcots koot su fo tser ehT
tsuj t’nod eW .rehtegoT
.noitasnes dna noitome otni nwod nekorb
.sevlesruo dnefed ot deen dluow ew
.rehtona yb depolevne dnim ruo dah su fo enO
.ylraelc tsom ees dluoc ,su fo tsegnuoy eht dna ,selggog htiw su fo esohT
.nus eht morf seye ruo tcetorp ot ksam krad a htiw
,stfihs artxe dekrow eW
.enola og reh tel ton dluow ew dna
,sgel ekil serutaef elbasingocer tuohtiw duolc sselmrof A
.gnitnuh tnew ew nehT
.ssenrehtegot fo dnik wen a saw tI
,enud eht dnuora dnas eht ni delttes dna
.deipuccoerp erew su fo lla dna
.xif ot slairetam dna emit suoicerp su tsoc taht sekatsim edam ew dna ,ypmuj tog eW
,enihsnus eht ni ,dnuorg evoba eb ot referp yeht yllaeR
,gniworrub rof dengised slian dna sdnah gnorts evah llits eW
.eno ekat I .eno deen I
.gnirevaw dna tsav
”stakreeM ereW eW ecnO“ :yojne esaelP
.dloh regnol on dluoc ecrof eht nehw tenalp siht fo emoceb dluow tahw wenk ew dna
.yawa edaf tenalp eht tlef dna
.meht tuoba togrof dna
,ytud s’redael reh od ot drawrof deppets ehS .ti dedne oM
,morf krow ot snalp fo knab tsav a evah thgim eW
retirw yrots trohs gninniw-drawa yb
boj tnerruc ruo no eye eno htiw dekrow ew os neve tub ,liated draug ot dengissa erew su fo eroM
.ecno ta lla meht delley ew dna ,snoitseuq dah ew woN .emac ew litnu—
stnemnorivne elitsoh htiw epoc ot dengised er’eW
,ti dellems ro ti draeh dah su fo ytnelP
.seiranoisiv neve ro
.lla su dleihs dluoc ehs fi sa
.sdneirf ruo ro gnuoy ruo rof gnikool
,efil dleh regnol on taht dlrow a no gniyd dna
:ecno ta ni ti koot lla eW
.stakreem erew ew ecnO
.dehceercs sneris eht elihw
.sregnits eht gnidiova elihw skcits htiw revo ti pilf ot gniyrt
.gnissim saw rebmun ruo fo rehtona deciton ew nehT
.ytic a dliub ot gniyrt tsuj erew eW
.elbisivni eht sa gniht hcus on saw ereht taht noisulcnoc eht ot su del
,retaw elttil deen eW
,ria detnecs-taem fo hsur a sa emac tI
,tnecs on ,stnirp on
”.ti od ll’I“ :dias su fo enO
,duolc taht otni pu depoocs saw su fo enO
.oot sretsnom elbisivni deen t’ndid eW
,tnew ew sa mrifni eht dna sdik pu gnipoocs
,ylimaf ro sdneirf ot eybdoog fo drow a tuohtiw ,sselnopaew
,srotaderp htiw laed ot hguone hguot llits er’eW
spihs ni evirra yeht ,tsal ta enod s’ti nehW
.tresed dna yks neewteb
nwonknu eht tnorfnoc dluow eW
sllec sti gniwener yb ti niatsus ton dluoc os dna
.snoitcurtsni wollof yldnilb
meht tlef osla ew tub
,dlo oot era owt esehT
,deksa su fo tser ehT
.depoord sdileye dna sraE
.gnimoc su draeh ti fi wol eil thgim erutaerc egral a erehw sworrub rof dna ,skcart rof dekool eW
.etamilc dna epacsdnal eht fo segatnavda dna smelborp ralucitrap eht ot esnopser ni tliub
erew eW  .ffuts diK
.llik ot ro etagitsevni ot eb dluohs noitarolpxe ruo fo mia eht rehtehw revo deugra eW
,ti tneverp ot od nac su fo yna gnihton s’ereht tub ,degaruocne yltcaxe ton s’tI
drawrof devom duolc ehT
.dniheb tfel ro yletomer gnikrow
,trohs erew sthgin ruO
,detneverp eb ot ton sa os ,terces a aedi rieht tpek su fo enO
llew meht dehsiw eW
?kcirt a ti saW .detabed eW
rehtegot dleh ylerab smota neewteb spag deniarts eht tlef eW
.selur nwo rieht ot gnidrocca efil wen a trats dna evael ot ediced su fo owt ro eno taht semitemos sneppah ti
enola saw erutaerc duolc eht taht egdelwonk eht
sthgin dloc eht ni mraw su speek taht ruf eht evah llits eW
.su rof t’nsi erac hcus htiw gnidliub er’ew ytic sihT
.aedi na dah su fo enO
neesnu ,yhtlaets ,tsav—
.evivrus ew woh s’tahT
,euqinu si etaerc ew ytic hcaE
sa pu dedne d’ohw swerc fo seirots htiw ,sdik sa ,rehto hcae deracs d’eW .seivom nees d’eW .derednow ew
.nwod su deneteiuq ,oM ,redael ruO
.meht barg dluoc ew erofeb ecnef eht hguorht gnicar dna sgel ruo neewteb gnirettiks ,sruof lla ot gnippord ,yawyna gnola dekaens yeht tub
.sloot evah osla ew hguoht neve
.devirra yeht nehw sreyolpme namuh ruo rof dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,yltnelis dnuora thguoht eht denrut su fo hcaE
.drawrof denarc ew dna
.sliat ruo tsol ew dna
.egnar lausu ruo dnoyeb ees su pleh ot
,mrala eslaf a ylbaborp saw ti taht tceffe eht ot tnemetats a edam oM
,dedulcnoc ew ,yaw rehtiE
,truh dekool meht fo enon tub
:stnemamra nwo ruo denoihsaf ylterces su fo emoS
.syevrus laitini eht yb dessim regnad neddih a slaever tenalp a nehw rof locotorp a s’erehT
,rulb gniwolg a dewohs selggog ehT
.nees eb t’ndluoc ti naem ton did
worrub sti fo tuo gubdnas a desaet yeht
.moc.tenalPruF ta dnif nac uoy hcihw
.gnirussaer tub edurc ,sbulc dna sevink
,sevlesruo mra ot detnaw ohw esoht dna
,dezis-namuh su edam yehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
rehtegot enud eht demraws eW
,smraerif sa llew sa snopaew lacirtcele dah ydaerla seirtnes ruO
,elcsum dilos era su fo lla toN
?fo diarfa os ew erew tahw
?enola tresed eht otni gniog deirt enoemos fi tahW
.etatneirosid dna elbasid ot dnuos desu taht epyt a dedda ew eseht ot dna
,skooB goD daB morf 01 emulov RAOR ni dehsilbup tsrif saw yrots sihT
,tsrif tnew tsevarb dna tsegnorts ruO
.thgif ro rekcib ton did eW
,spuorg otni tilpS
.monev fo sepyt emos ot enummi dna
,sdnim ruo hguorht selppir tnes rewsna ehT
?tahw roF .wenk won ew
.secnef dna sllaw ruo fo edistuo eht dnuora gniklats—
,erutnevda eht ta gnilggig dna gnikeirhs llitS
.secaps naenarretbus eht ni dna sllaw lennut eht gnola lla sthgil era ereht os ,sruo sa doog sa t’nera seye riehT .meht rof s’tI
.efildliw yrotaderp dna
.tnemele deifsitassid yna fo dir eb ot tseb s’ti spahrep dna
,secnef eht dnoyeb tuo kaens ot esohc sreganeet ruo fo puorg a thgin kcalb ,dloc enO
.yawa ro sdrawot gnillup ,dnas eht ni delffucs su fo emos dna ,seciov ruo desiar eW
.emac tI  .nwonknu eht rof detiaw dna
.gnidliub dna gniggid erew su fo tsoM
,htraE tfel ydaerla dah spihs namuh ehT
.ylppus retaw eht pu gnittes smelborp gnivah erew ew dna
.niaga teews lla s’ti dna ,eson eht no esle enoemos spob enoemos ro ,rehtegot sdaeh wef a kconk ot sah oM esac tsrow eht nI
,retsnom eht ta dekool dna ,snopaew fo kcal a etartsnomed ot ediw tuo sdnah derruf daerps su fo enO  .hteet ro ,seye
.reffo eht deredisnoc eW
.htiw dnetnoc ot sekans gnipmuj dna shtuomelkcirp
.eludehcs dniheb saw ytic ehT  .ysub erew eW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.ycrem tuohtiw mih desaet ew dna ,syar-dnim neila sa debircsed eh tahw morf niarb sih tcetorp ot seriw fo temleh a edam su fo enO
.esabatad eht ni serutcip nees ev’eW
retsnom fo dnik emoS
.neeb evah dluohs ew sa tnaligiv sa ton erew eW
.ooz neila emos ni stibihxe
.enoyreve rof t’nsi ti tub
mrala eht desiar d’ohw yrtnes eht fo dloh tog ehS
.noitcetorp dna ruobal rof tliub
.krow gnidliub eht htiw ni dehctip sboj rehto ot dengissa yllausu su fo esoht dna
.dnatsrednu dluoc ew ssol fo dnik eht saw ,tsael ta ,siht tub ,ekans gnipmuj a ot srethgif ruo fo eno tsol eW
krow thgin rof esu ew selggog eht detpada ew oS
,emoh fo ytefas eht rof delf yeht
?sllems ynnuF ?seirotS ?stsohG
.smra rieht ni nerdlihc dleh stneraP
.senips ruo no ruf eht desiar dna
.morf ward nac srehto dna werc ruo taht egdelwonk fo mus eht ot gnidda
,sgubdnas dah ydaerla eW
,kcab emoc t’ndid owt gnissim ruO
,sdrow reh draeh eW
.nepo deknilb seyE
.tuo reh denword ew tub
metsys noitagirri eht no gnikrow neeb d’ohw ,sreenigne eht fo eno dna
,meht rof semoh dezis-namuh dliub nac ew os
.thgin dna yad eht fo sruoh tnereffid ta deirt eW .gnihtoN
.dloc dna kcalb tub
.dnim nwo ruo ni hcae
,krow ruo htiw no yrrac ot erew eW
.esoprup evah ew esuaceB
,reetyksuH yb ”stakreeM ereW eW ecnO“
.rettam suoires a s’tI
,detalosi neeb dah nekat erew ohw seno ehT .esruoc fo ,spuorg ni gnillortap ruo enod dah eW
,meht tlef neila eht sa
,meht ot egassem a teg ot elba neeb d’ew fi neve dna
.ni ti dewolla noitartnecnoc ruo ro ssenllits ruo ,ecnelis ruO
si yrots s’yadoT    dna
,yad eht fo taeh eht ni looc dna
.su fo tser eht morf yawa tfird ot nageb dniheb dneirf rieht tfel dna thgin tresed eht morf yawa nur d’ohw sdik ehT
.meht rof kool ot tuo dedaeh seitrap hcraes dna
.derettahc ro derepsihw ydoboN
.yrots ym nageb I oS  .dias ti ,em lleT
tnelis llef yehT
,tsol ruo rof dna ,sevlesruo rof
.dellortap ew dna serauqs otni esab ruo gnidnuorrus tresed eht dedivid ew
,rehto hcae revo dereep dna ecnef eht ot pu deldduh eW
,ykcirt saw niarret ehT
.su rof rO .meht rof doof dna ecaps hguone ton dna ,gnimocni sluos fo sdnasuoht evah dluow eW
,tnorf yrev eht ta ,llat pu flesreh werd oM
.wolloh devrac-dniw hcae gnillif
saw yrots sihT   -------
.dniheb rehtruf reve llef krow gnidliub ehT
thgin eht otni tuo deklaw su fo enO
.regnad rof sredluohs ruo revo gnicnalg rehto eht dna
,etile rieht rof gninoitidnoc-ria htiw sesuoh otni secruoser dna emit fo tol a ruop ot evah ew slenap ralos eht pu gnittes sa llew sa os
.esnepxe dna elbuort fo laed taerg a tuohtiw kcab denrut evah ton dluoc yeht
ti fo kniht ot emac ew won
.yawa nur ro tniaf ton did dna
.gnihtyna tsomla tae nac ew dna
,yerp rieht dnuora gnicnad erew yeht elihw saw tI
snoissucsid dna hcraeser ruO
,etis ruo dnetxe ot ecalp tseb eht rof aera eht gnikcehc tuo ,royevrus a
.ereh dnuora gnihtyna no dil a peek ot elbissopmi s’ti
,ytud yrtnes no erew su fo emoS
.sanera strops dna skrap decnef ylefas otni dna
;gniylf ydaerla erew sruomur eht tuB
.rekcalb emoceb thgin eht dna edaf thgilrats eht deciton yeht taht
.ssam a ni doots dna
!etis eht dekcip d’ohw srennalp eht ,oN !sreenigne ehT !oN .tluaf ’sreggid eht saw tI
.etuc eb ot desu eW
.gnihtaerb erew yeht dna
,gnikeirhs dna gnilggig
.dlrow wen rieht ot ni evom dna
.ecnef eht dnuora retsulc dna
:troper ot gnihton htiw denruter eW
,ku.oc.reetyksuh ta reh dnif nac uoY .reetyksuH
,spuorg ro sriap ni emac su fo tser ehT
,gnuoy oot eno siht dna
.emoh llac nac ew taht ecalp on s’erehT
,tcejorp a no emit artxe ni tup ot enola gnikrow sevlesruo dnuof netfo eW
.sdnuob gnikaerb rof ni erew yeht elbuort eht fo tuo edils ot yrots a pu gnikam tsuj erew yeht thguoht eW
,no gniog gnihtemos saw ereht tuo erugif ot tsrif erew sdik elttil ruO .sag naht erom
.sneppah reven tahT .dedivid
,ti etavitca ot dedeen reven d’eW
.niaga revo lla trats ot ,tenalp demialcnu txen eht ot su yrrac neht spihs esohT
,stsitra sa sevlesruo ebircsed su fo emoS
,elihw a ti ta dekop dna
?wam sti otni tser eht erul ot su fo eno gniteppup won saw taht retsnom a ot rehtona tsol ew daH
.seneg ruo ni si ytinU
.tnelis siht reven erew eW
,evisnopsernu dna desolc seye
,sredluohs ruo no snopaew
.slliks ruo dnoyeb yaw dna epocs ruo edistuo saw siht tuB
.gnirob gniht elohw eht dnuof dna tnedicca yb ereht erew yeht fi sa kool ot gniyrt ,swodahs eht fo tuo knuls sreganeet ruo nehT
,dellac oM ”,emit a ta enO“
,duolc yggof eht ni gnimrof sepahs fo erawa emaceb eW
.noziroh eht fo enil eht ni noitrotsid a dna
.rehtegotla tuo llup ot detnaw su fo emoS
goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.yletavirp ti detucexe dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.secnef eht raen tuo
”,uoy fo llA .ereh tuo emoc dluohs uoy kniht I“
.dnuora selggog fo sriap ruo gnissap
.hgih uoy tog raews ot gnilliw syawla erew su gnoma emos taht sutcac fo dnik a rof gnikool
enil eht tuo gnittolb ssenkrad fo hctap a ees ot pu dekool dna
;rehtegot ffo nur dah reenigne dna royevrus ruo taht dedulcnoc eW
,ruf rieht gnilffur dniw dloc eht htiw
.stsitneics dna snaicinhcet ,stcetihcra era eW
eno dnif t’ndid yeht nehW
.ekil dekool ti tahw yas dluoc su fo enon tub
,srepeek-drocer era su fo emoS
.semoh namuh otni stenalp tresed nrut ot si esoprup elohw ruO
.kcatta morf efas su tpek taht spuorg eht ni gnikcits naht rehtar
derit erew su fo llA
.esac ni tsuj ecnaligiv hgih artxe gniniatniam
:gnissim owt erew erehT
.etutitsbus dna esivorpmi ot deen netfo ew os ,tnereffid si tenalp yreve tub
.dah ohw werc yna fo draeh ew dah ron
”.rehtegot kcits eW .ylimaf er’eW“ .dias oM ”,laed oN“
,ynoloc wen rieht rof dnuob
.rehto hcae rof tuo kool llits ew ,lla fo tsoM
.dellac su fo eno
enud a pota tas dna
.tnemetats a reh evig dluoc eh os edisa mih koot dna
,pu delruc yal yehT .gnissim ruO
.melborp wen siht no krow ot tes seiranoisiv dna stsitneics eW
.meht dloh dna nwod nur ot yawa ekorb su fo emoS
,ekil su fo tsom taht efil a s’tI
”stakreeM ereW eW ecnO“