,segnul drapoel ehT
.sfeiler cirtemoeg ni senots suoicerpimes htiw dialni doow aus htiw yltnelupo detaroced
.esactius ym gnibbarg ,pu dnats dna
,nrut syek eht sA
,rehtael fo xim a
tnerappa si yradnuob evitcnitsid A
”.elbat taraccaB eht ta now I tahw ylesicerp
sniamer roolf revetahw gnilliF
.em fo tnorf ni sevlehs doowesor dehsilop no degnarra ylnotnaw
.ruf naht rehtaew suoutsepmet ni ylurnu erom raf era srehtaeF
,toofa feiht a si ereht fI
.detsaw tfel hcni na ton
”!emoh ta tiftuo ym naht retteb stif tI“
,krowrehtael etisiuqxe htiw detaroced si roiretxe ehT
,skramdnal lacirotsih wef a morf edisA
,riahc gnikoms tevlev eht ni kcab skcik retto ykcots ehT
”.stuobaerehw sih fo swonk ro ,mih swonk ohw enoemos dnif ll’ew dnuora gniksa yb spahreP
.hctawtsirw sih skcehc ahsiM
,mih fo tnorf ni lwob eht ypucco seldoon wef A
knis eht ediseb morf tnemragrednu nottoc a barg I
.sucof otni semoc ahsiM litnu semit wef a knilb neht dna
.renaelc muucav a uoy lles ot ereh ton era eW“
.walc xedni sih morf syek fo tes a gnilgnad
.tellug sih nwod elttob eht spit eh sa ,syas eh
.stekcop tnorf sih otni sgninniw eht skcut eh sa aloC-
?letoh eht ta kcab htab gnixaler a ekat uoy t’nod yhW“
.esidarap tsilatipac a si siht woN“
ro…slevart ym gnirud hguone netfo dnif tonnac I yruxul a ,retaw toh tnadnuba si ereht ,llitS
s’ahsiM ”?wen gnihtemos ees oT
.ytlaiceps ym reven saw tabmoc wap-ot-
.senotselbboc eht tsniaga srettiks tI
ngis noen eht ylnO
,retrauQ dlO eht etisoppo sdnats retrauQ hcnerF eht erehw
.ebordraw suomrone na gnivom star dleif ecir fo maet a hguorht gniwolp diova ot thgir eht ot drah su stlit dna sekarb eht no smals ahsiM ”!ti nmaD“
tuhs skcilc tals ehT         ”.ro'd rosért el edrag rihpas ed nogard eL“         ”? essap ed tom el tse leuQ“ .ytilibaturcsni decitcarp htiw
.hself eht no spit ekilfael
,sretem derdnuh-owt fo edutitla na ta gnisiurc er’eW
.spihsria gnivirra rof tniop gnikcod a gnimrof
.ecnarF ni naht elbixelf erom laed taerg a raeppa ereh swal daoR
.rolrap gnilbmag a ot daeh s’teL“
,ennairaM sdnuorrus retrauQ hcnerF ehT
.degagne evah spmalc gnikcod citengamortcele eht em sllet knuht duol A
.ylreporp stif ti taht eeS“
”?llorts ruoy no tekraM thgiN eht yb pots uoy diD“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.senigne eht fo raor tneibma eht evoba yrrac ot hguone eciov ym esiar I
”!noitacav ruo fo tser eht yojne nac ew taht os ssenisub ylgu siht fo erac ekat ot emiT“
,ionaH fo dne nretsew eht ni si rolrap gnimag nogarD erihppaS ehT         *** ”.evird ll’I“
”!kcab nioc taht teg ew taht evitarepmi si ti nehT“
.lanimret eht ni tlah ot rotavele eht rof setunim wef a tub sekat tI
.ragic detropmi na mih sdnah retiaw a sa
?qcaJ lleW“         .xiabuoR ni
,ediw fo esnapxe na
.teerts gniltsub eht nwod gnicar
.tcirtsid éronoH-tniaS gruobuaF eht fo snoihsaf tsetal eht ni
.yaw eht dael ot ahsiM rof gnirutseg
emorhc ni derutpac
.tnemtrapa tsrif ym esahcrup ot hguone edam d’I
.ebolg eht ssorcssirc ot yaw suoiruxul tsom eht sa sutats sti gniyleb
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ereh su del ecilop lacol eht ot llac enohpelet kciuq A
.sduolc eht hguorht gnikaerb cnalB tnoM ekil skool kaeb ym litnu selbbub ni flesym yrub I ,letoh eht tA
,tauqs era sgnidliub ehT
.noihsaf ylredro na ni krabmesid esaelP
.yawrood dessecer eht fo sedis htob knalf
.ylmrif spar dna rood ymirg eht sehcaorppa ahsiM
.dael ot ahsiM rof gnirutseg
denaelc dna delbmessasid neeb sah roterubrac ehT“
”.tseuqer ruoy rep ,dellatsni thgildaeh hserf a dna
.ffo egaggul ruo pord ylbaborp dluohs ew ,gnippohs ni dessorgne oot teg ew erofeB“
.ffo naelc snottub s’tekcaj eht fo eno ecils swalc s’drapoel eht sa
.drawni skaerc rood eht tub
?sruoh owt ni siht lla delbmessa uoY“
,spalf tekcop tsaerb eht ot dennip era
ymedaca ecilop lanoitan eht morf detaudarg I yad eht ecnis prahs siht dekool t’nevah I
.cilohocla na yb degrof lleb a fo ydolem eht lla htiw
”?yawyna ti si emit tahW“
.ytic eht fo traeh eht hcaorppa ew sa su semoclew troporea ehT
”,devirra evah ot raeppa eW“
”.etarg rewes a nwod ti deppord eh dna diputs si dneirf ruoy ebyaM
.teerts eht no yb dessap I fi kool dnoces a ti evig t’ndluow I
noziroh sseldnuob ehT
”.esicerp erom eb ot ,kcolc’o enin rO“ .snirg ahsiM
.slirtson sih morf ylizal gnitfird ekoms eht
snoitarepo fo esab ’seveiht eht ot klaw gnixaler a s’tI
.hgih sretem ytfif derdnuh-eno ylraen sdnats ennairaM fo eutats eht
.ni nihtiw noitagitsevni na gnitcudnoc naht ytic a wonk ot teg ot yaw retteb on s’ereht
.kaeb ym gnikcilc ,ylpeed nway I ”?woN“
.tekcop tekcaj edisni ym otni kcab sesioluaG fo kcap eht edils dna hgis I ,tnilf ym nwod raew naht rehtaR
acoC dna akdov a sredro eH .em sniojer dna
.deeps war htiw ahsiM mlehwrevo ot gnikees
snaej mined elyts-naciremA ni
.gnineve siht slliks gnitaitogen tseb rieht thguorb ylerus sah enoyrevE
.elituf era ezalba etteragic ym tes ot stpmetta ym ,sdniw hgih eht tsniaga rethgil ym dleihs I hguohT
a si ecremmoc gniltsub taht ni trap ekat oT
erihppas a dnuora gnilruc nogard esenihC a—
.gnag   eht htiw s’eH
.ezniuQ-etnaxioS a no gnippis ,rab eht morf yllausac evresbo I
segdab revlis ytfeH
,hcae seirots eerht ro owt
secaf ruo ni rood eht mals ot troffe s’drapoel ehT
nus gnisir a fo sfitoM
”.noitats eht ot revo rednaem ylbaborp dluohs eW
”.wal eht fo ytirohtua eht eriuqca ot yaw a si ereht taht si dezilaer ev’I tahW“
.ysatnaf dna ,noitcif ecneics ,acitore
”.ereht sretcarahc ydahs fo egatrohs on eb lliw ereht erus m’I
?letoh eht rof ragic ruoy evas ton yhW“
”.ereh raf etiuq og ot smees yenoM“
.seye sih sllor ahsiM
.anihcodnI hcnerF hguorht tpews sah taht ytinredom rof tsul eht fo smitciv era yeht
.rus neiB“         ”.dneirfyob ym htiw gnineve citnamor a fo yaw eht ni gnitteg gnihtyna tnaw t’nod I
”.edis ruo no wal eht fo ytirohtua eht evah lliw ew esoppus I ,oS“
zapot wolley fo seceip fo snezod fo demrof rats gnirettilg a erats I
”?edam eseht evah ot tsoc ti hcum woh wonk
.ragic sih gnithgil-er ,selkcuhc ahsiM
”.tisiv a neyugN rueisnoM yam ew erofeb od tsum I gnihtemos s’erehT
.elbat eht no tellaw rehtael kcalb a stes ahsiM
”.flesym eldnah nac I
”.scnarf noillim a ekil skooL“
”.edarmoc ,uoy knahT“
”.noitacav eno rof ionaH fo hguone tuoba dah ev’I kniht I“
.thgir ym ot relddep a yb tfola dleh ionaH akdoV fo elttob a seye eH
.ezis sih elbuod ot esolc tsaeb ralucsum a
.tekcaj eht pu nottub I sa
.sthgif ni ytilibarud kcal senob wolloH
”!eerga tsum redneg eht
.elttob ssalg llat a morf reeB 33 a gniyojne
,7 GNAF gnidulcni
”.egasu daor rof ydaer s’ti kniht I tub ,epytotorp a s’tI
.tsehc ym ni ecnedifnoc fo llews a secudorp thgiew railimaf ehT
secnediser dna sletoh elbanoihsaf era tuohguorht desrepsretnI
.taoc s’naitamlad a fo em sdnimer tI
,sedohR fo sussoloC nredom A
.noom lluf tnaillirb a rednu tserof lufecaep a stciped tI
.seveiht eht fo ecart on s’erehT
.sredluohs ym morf selbbub eht gniraelc dna
;skcal rewop maets taht retcarahc war a sah tI
”.nwod ti kcik yllanosrep lliw I ro rood siht nepO
stsipyt decitcarp fo mhtyhr eht htiw yawa gnikcilc snortap
.sserP lesaeW yb detubirtsid ,krowteN wohS emaG yrruF ehT
,elbat eht no teef sih stser ahsiM
”!mih morf yawa teG !uoy ,yeH“
,regna fo ssih wol a s’erehT
,nrets tub mraw si egasiv detplucs ylenif reH
.moordeb eht otni sdaeh dna
,racedis dehcatta na htiw elcihev gnikool-ydruts a si ekib s’ahsiM
”!puocuaeb icrem ,resare emadam ro licnep rueisnom
.yrotcaF elcycotuA neveS rebmuN eht ta enil eht ffo dellor yltnecer tsuj tI
edis eht ot segdod eH
”–deen dluow uoy ,taht od oT ?os woH“
.sbir s’drapoel eht otni woble sih sevird dna
?noitacav a fo tniop eht ton taht sI“
”!thgis ni gnihtyna esahcrup ot enil a t’nsi erehT
”! énisiuc tnemehcîarf te duahC ! ohP“         ”! xid retehca ne siod uT ! selatsop
.llorts a ekat s’teL“         ”?uohc nom ,seY“
.esaelp yeht sa ssorc ot
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
seye ym esolc ylfeirb I
”.noélopaN fo yrusaert eht desivrepus yllanosrep rehtafdnarg taerg-taerg-taerg-taerg ym nehw morf tellaw taht ni nioc dlog a tpek I“
latipac eht ni yats ruoy yojne uoy epoh eW
.tellaw ruoy tuoba yrros ma I“
.niard rewes eht otni thgiarts seog ti erofeb eye ym fo renroc eht fo tuo skraps tnarre wef a hctac I
.eye eht steem naht ecalp siht ot erom si ereht taht stnih—
,enutrof llamS“         ” –a tsoc ev’tsum tahT
”.gnilrad ,eye tnellecxe
,elzzum sih snroda racs dekciw A
”ionaH ni yaD enO“
.sepip tsuahxe niwt eht morf tips emalf fo stsrub sa gninediw nirg sih
”!lla ton si taht tub ,hO“
.niahcyek eht gninroda elkcis dna remmah lemane na eciton I
.ecilop evitan eht yonna ot dednetni ylbaborp noitca na
”?qcaJ thgir ,esae ta dnim eht tup ot noitacav a ekil gnihtoN“
sessetsoh deye-prahS
”.siraP ni noitacav rieht morf gninruter sreciffo ecilop ytud-ffo owt morf gnilaets fo ekatsim etanutrofnu eht edam uoY“
.tekcaj loow eretsua na dna
noitca tlob eht ekil
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,elddup a ni denodnaba
.noitacav siht ekil tsuj ,teewsrettib dna gnorts s’tI
.rethgil yllaitnatsbus gnileef ylneddus tekcop kcab ym ,drawpu krej I
.ecnalg gninoitseuq a mih toohs I
.taoc gnineve sih fo loow tfos eht no daeh ym tser ot revo nael I ”.ahsiM hO“
.snaiva ot retac sroliat wef os ecnis stnemerusaem htiw krowsseug emos did I
.oopmahs detnecs-doowladnas ,yklis eht yawa gnisnir
;flesti tellaw eht tuoba reven saw tI“ .elkcuhc I
.ezeerb ffits eht ni gnilffur srehtaef ym ,ionaH fo
”?noissim siht tuoba og ew od woH
.retoocs gnitiaw a fo kcab eht otno spael eh
.ohp fo gnivres ytraeh a fo stnanmer eht
noitan a fo ecaf eht
.emit emos ni dah ev’I nuf tsom eht si siht
but eht ediseb eenk a gnikat ,selkcuhc ahsiM
.tuhs smals rood moorhtab ehT
.esac sih ot ti snruter dna tuo ti sffuns ahsiM
.htaenrednu eeffoc rettib eht ot hguorht kaerb I erofeb klim desnednoc fo reyal pot eht fo ssenteews mraw eht gniyojne ,pis a ekat I
***  .dworc eht sehsinav neht dna
.flesmih thgir ot stpmetta tac eht sa kcoldaeh a ni feiht eht stup eH
.rennid erofeb rettam siht elttes s’teL“
.yltnedifnoc ni sedirts ahsiM
”.owt ro rinevuos a pu kcip ot emit eb thgim ereht os ,ruoh na ni sevael niart ehT“
.revlover eussi-ecilop a rof tnaem redloh a gniruces
.teerts eht nwod gnitrats dna wap sih gnibbarg
na evah uoY“ .kniw I
ionaH ni yad eno ,yas yeht sA
.feiht eht nwod gnirats ,syas ahsiM
,ydob eht fo cirbaf nat eht tsniaga tuo dnats srehtaef eulb yM
!ahsiM“ .ionaH ni sedivorp mrofinu a noitcetorp dna ytirohtua eht detamitse-revo evah yam eW
”?naem uoy od tahW“
.teerts eht otni gniylf ti gnidnes dna dnah ym morf ti gnikcik
,sevirra rotavele ehT !gniD
.nogarD erihppaS eht ta uoy gnivael retfa htimsrevlis eht dna roliat eht ot revo dehsur I“
spahreP“ .sedirts wef a ni rotavele eht dna moor ruo neewteb ecnatsid trohs eht srevoc eH
”.noitatropsnart deleehw-owt sreferp ereh enoyreve smees tI
.trac oobmab ytekcir a no knird eeffoc a gniraperp relles teerts a ot revo srednaw yldednimtnesba eH
”,enola uoy evael ll’ew dna tellaw eht nruteR“
.reviR gnokeM eht fo seiratubirt eht ekil teerts eht nwod wolf tekraM thgiN eht ot srotisiv ylrae ehT
”.uoy esirprus ot tnaw I .tnemom a rof desolc seye ruoy peeK
.aera lanimret lartnec eht otni selitsnrut eht hguorht pets ew tnemom eht su revo speews ytic eht fo eltsub eht
.taraccaB gniyalp rof selbat era
,os ro ruoh flah txen eht revO
.dnuorg eht ot su trocse ot stiawa leets sselniats ni delenap rotavele suonrevac A
.detacoler neeb ylegral evah ytsanyD nễyugN eht fo syad yrolg eht morf sgnidliub redlo ehT .elyts
,snepo rood eht ,retal tnemom A
.éhcraM noB uA ta scnarf owt rof elas no ti desahcrup I
.seidob fo ssam dekcap ylesned eht ta daeh ym ekahs dna yella worran a nwod kool I
,su stiawa maN teiV fo
.emit suoicerp esol ew
.niagrab a fo hcraes ni
.nirg yls a em stoohs ahsiM
meht ssim ew hcihw yb nigram ehT
.ylgnivorppa don I
.deeps pu kcip ot sraeg stfihs ahsiM
keehc ym no ssik thgil a stisoped ahsiM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.racedis eht otni flesym gniws ot mutnemom eht esu dna redluohs s’ahsiM psarg I
.ima nom ,tsaf os toN“
”!siht htiw yawa teg mih tel t’noD !mih retfA“
,su ot snokceb wap thgir reh ni tfola dleh raeps dnarg ehT
,ecnamor gnidulcni
emit ni tsuj kcab spets ahsiM
!ha ...tub ,erauqS deR ni erots tnemtraped MUG eht ton ylniatrec s’tI“
.sredluohs ym dnuora mra na sparw ahsiM ”?tif eht s’woH
.nward snug htiw ni og dna rood tnorf sih nwod kcik ylpmis tonnac eW“ .daeh ym ekahs I
,tnecsed ruo nigeb eW
.pirt siht dennalp ohw eno eht er’uoY
.syella worran dna
.htab eht ni ffo detfird evah tsum I
rorrim eht ni flesym erimda I
”!ragic ym til tsuj I kniht oT !haB“
,tuo niht ot nugeb evah sdworc ehT
,ffup peed a sekat eH
.lla ti gniylrednu ksum fo hcuot a tsuj htiw
”?nalp a evah uoy oD“
yltnalahcnon wap a spilf ahsiM
.yalni lraep-fo-rehtom htiw draob nedoow llams a tuo sllup ahsiM ”!siht ta kooL
”?feiht eht tuoba gnihtyna tuo dnif uoy diD“
”?gniod er’uoy tahw wonk uoy erus uoy erA“
,denrawerof eB“
.rovaf reh meht stnarg kcuL ydaL taht epoh eht ni
.xobllac ecilop a dnif dna sffuc eht teg ,qcaJ“
.elzzum-ot-elzzum
.elbur revlis a mih spilf ahsiM
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
tuoedih rieht taht nrael ot deganam I
,nioc derusaert ym tsol evah ot yppahnu ylniatrec m’I elihW
”.won meht nepo nac uoY“
ylreporp ees ot maof hguone yawa hsurb ot ecaf ym revo walc a nur I         ”?qcaJ“
.eye sih ni maelg a ,sdon ahsiM
”.tah a fo tuo snuon ruo fo sredneg eht kcip t’nod eW
.gnippohs fo tib a did I“
.wolley dratsum fo edahs ddo na detniap
.tnemesuma htiw strons ahsiM
,gnitivni dna mraw si tnecs siH
steerts gnidniw fo tnemegnarra cinagro na otni
.srettum ahsiM ”,tuoba gniklat m’I tahw wonk od uoy os ,hA“
.tnatsni na ni ragic sih setingi rethgil s’reciffo teivoS ytud-yvaeh
”.em ksa uoy fi ,rovalf eht sniur edutitla ehT
”.esira yeht nehw deyojne eb tsum seitinutroppo esehT
,ytirohtua fo reggaws citsiretcarahc eht htiW
.desolc rood evitcetorp eht sllup rotarepo rotavele detius-eulb eht
.elbaccepmi si pihsnamstfarc ehT
.tnemeticxe htiw pu gnirps I
,spoocs otni swap debbew sih gnimroF
.emarf eht dna rood eht neewteb ecaps worran eht otni ti segdew eh sa toob rehtael-tnetap s’ahsiM yb dekcolb si
.edis ruo no wal eht fo ytirohtua eht evah ton od eW
”,kcab tellaw sih ekil dluow ereh dneirf derehtaef yM“
,retrauQ hcnerF eht fo lacipyt si erutcurts ehT         ”.si ti ereH“
.tnahpmuirt degreme dna
”!dlrow eht dnuora yawflah pu dne ot tcepxe t’ndid I ,eciffo ym fo senifnoc eht epacse ot tnuaj elttil a detseggus uoy nehW“
”!yrassecen fi ,lliw ew tub ,uoy eudbus ot tnaw ton od eW“
,tamhtab nottoc yvaeh eht otno pets I sa noos sa ffo em gniyrd snigeb eH
.swalc sih sdnetxe drapoel eht sa tnilg a hctac I
”.evirra seitirohtua lacol eht erofeb mih etagorretni ll’I
.ecnats evissergga na gnimussa ,syas ahsiM
si yltnedicnioc si hcihw
.letoh ruo morf elcycrotom etunim-ytnewt luftnevenu na s’tI
,serneg ynam ni gnitirw syojne ohw rohtua nainigriV a si
,revlover ym ward I
.worbeye na gnisiar
egami eht htiw denroda eceip dlog ytfeh eht erimda I
noitaroproC nileppeZ noinU teivoS eht fo mrofinu yarg eretsua eht ni desserd lakcaj nedlog A
?qcaJ ,kniht uoy od tahW“
.tnemnorivne siht ni truh t’nac eniniuq ehT
?lufituaeb ti t’nsI“
dnatsthgin eht ffo revlover enneitE .tS ytsurt ym barg ot moordeb eht ot kcab daeh I
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.deyonna m’I won dnA“
.raeg tsrif segagne ahsiM sa slrans enigne ehT         ”!oG“
,nwod drapoel eht serats eh sa selims eH
mrofinu owt eht fo rellat eht em sdnah ahsiM
”?elbur eht htiw etar egnahcxe eht s’tahW“         ”.gnorts si ti
?tnaw sreppoc uoy od tahW“
.llehs sulituan a ekil kool ot delyts
em ta erats seye neerg suonimuL
.ekaL mếiK nàoH fo
”.nioc taht fo ssol eht terger ylno I
”.suoiciled s’tI .siht yrT“
.cinot dna nig a flesym redro I
.mus elbaredisnoc a pu s’eh
,drawrof toohs eW
.dlohserht desiar eht no spirt eh sa nwod seog drapoel eht
”.esiaçnarF enihcodnI'l ed eciloP“
”!knird a flesruoy yuB“
,sserd s’reciffo teivoS a fo eulb peed eht morf erutraped a s’tI
.relevart a fo tiftuo suoucipsnocni eht s’tI
.yaj eulb laref a fo ngised eht mrof ot
.llaw raf eht gnola tuo sehcterts rab A
”.sreidlos wollef ym htiw tnorF nretsaE eht fo sehcnert eht ni yalp ot desu I“ .sdon eH
,gnidliub yrots-owt denrodanu na ni desuoH
.su evoba blub dekan eht yb nworht thgil mid eht ni gniwolg seninac fo riap railimaf a
,su fo tnorf ni sezilairetam
”.tnemetats a sekam ylniatrec tI“
rehtegot deloot rehtael fo sdnarts gnitsiwt ynam
eniwt htiw kcar egaggul raer eht ot sesactius ruo sehsal ahsiM
ueida sreyalp rehto eht sdib eh
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”ionaH ni yaD enO“
?he ,wal eht fo ytirohtuA“         ”.edis
.snepo etag saduJ eht
.ezeeuqs a em sevig ahsiM
.selbat eht fo eno ot sdaeh yletaidemmi ahsiM
”.egamulp ruoy etadommocca ot moor artxe htiw nwes tekcaj ruoy dah I
htmraw fo hsur A
raeppa ohw snairtsedep fo maerts suounitnoc a egdod yeht sa seuneva enotselbboc gnitagivan
,ecyoR-slloR a fo taht sa hsulp si teprac ehT
”?gniklat eht od I llahs rO ?hcnerF ruoy decitcarp uoy evaH
”?melborp ruoy si tahW .eniF“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”,elbaccepmi si liated ot noitnetta ruoy ,yas tsum I“
,lortep tnrubnu dna ,occabot
,tnemegdelwonkca fo don thgils a htiW
.elbappalfnu si erusserp rednu erusopmoc s’ahsiM
.delleps era sdrow yaw eht yb sgniht eseht llet nac uoy naissuR ni ,wonk uoY“
.cangoc hcum oot raf demusnoc sah siuoL elcnU ym retfa yaD ellitsaB ekil tsuj sleef tI
,htab eht ot txen retnuoc eht ffo lewot a sbarg ahsiM
eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
,reciffo na stifeb sA
”.siraP t’nsi sihT
”ionaH ni yaD enO“
,ffo sekat revird ehT
,dekcap si roiretni ehT
,ecnalab ffo mih sworht tnemevom ylneddus ehT
weiv cimaronap a srotisiv wolla ot swodniw htiw dettod si
.ytic eht edistuo tsuj denim
.lewot eht edisa sessot ahsiM sa thgil eht ot pu segdab eht fo eno gnidloh ,rettum I
.nibac niam eht tsap gnimaerts ria psirc eht yojne ot hguone wol
”.tnemtrapa ym ni ti gnah ot tiaw tonnac I
.ecaep evitaler ni erehpsomta thgin gnihserfer eht yojne ot su gniwolla
.murht nevenu na htiw gnitanoser eldi eht
.snretnal cirtcele htiw til ylmid reyof a gnilaever
”.setatilicaf retnuoc eht nopu seton fo kcats egral a ecivres fo level eht gnizama s’tI
.sgnidliub evitartsinimda detniap-wolley yb dednuob seuneva denil-eert
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”.ereh morf skcolb wef a tsuj si tuoedih ’seveiht eht eveileb I
uoy oD“ ffo flesmih stsud eh sa.selkcunk sih skcarc ahsiM
”?siht retfa ot erehw ,oS“
,semit wef a ti rotom eht sver retto yM
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”.ylkciuq eussi siht sserdda ll’ew dna revlover ym teg ll’I“ .selkcuhc ahsiM
tnaillirb strap lauqe si taht lauqe nalp a fo stnemele eht era em erofeB
.rehtaef a gnikculp yltnedicca diova ot erusserp eltneg gniylppa
”.edarmoc ,ekib ruoY“
.rood eht fo kcab eht no gnah
.puc repap a em sreffo ahsiM ”?eeffoc ggE“
si ti rehtehw gninimreted straf dlo elbaegdelwonk ylemertxe fo draob a evah ew wonk uoy evah lliw I“
.dnammoc larutan fo ria na htiw mrofinu eht sraew eH
,oitap eht fo roolf elbram eht tsniaga separcs gel riahc a fo latem ehT
.tnorf tuo gniworg nedrag delevehsid ,llams a htiw emohnwot yrots-owt a
.ytic eht fo evitcepsrep tnereffid a su gnivig llaw retuo eht pu gnikam wodniw ssalg cimaronap eht
elubitsev desolcne eht tuohguorht seohce dnuos ehT
.stsiruot gnitcepsusnu no syerp taht guht teerts a si neyugN rueisnoM .gnihtyna noitnem t’ndid regit ehT“         ”?mih
,tiurf eht otni ecils dna efinknep ytsurt ym eveirter I
.eraps ot moor htiw elbat enol eht ta emag a otni flesmih stresni yllausac ahsiM
”.stellaw dna sesrup gnihctans ni ssenisub ksirb a s’ereht erus m’I
”!letoh eht ,sey ,hO“
.siraP ot kcab ekat ot srinevuos latneiro emos esahcrup ot tiaw tonnac I
,tekcaj hcae fo tnorf eht ssorca pih ot redluohs snur parts rehtael-ortep ,kciht A
.flah em gnidnah dna owt ni etteugab ypsirc eht gnikaerb
,srevocer ahsiM hguohT
xuaF .eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
,hguoht timda tsum I
.enigne noitsubmoc lanretni eht pu serif neht dna
llib eht revoc ot elbat eht no snioc wef a pord I
.ahsiM ,reciffo ecilop doog ytterp a ekam uoY“
,rood eht no skconk kciuq eerht gniwolloF
,sdnah wef a retfA
.dnats ot em rof gnirutseg
,etib tsal ym hsinif I sA .sarg eiof ton dna
.thguoht gnillirht
.rof depoh dah I eton gnixaler eht no nugeb ton sah noitacav sihT
,sdrawni skaerc rood ehT .elfir a fo
*** ”?ima nom ,won tellaw taht tuoba klat ot ydaer uoy erA“
”.retrauQ hcnerF eht ni sreisoR ed euR 511 ta si
.liat sih no talf sllaf eh dna
tuoba elbakramer gnihtynA“
.tekcop sih ni dnuora sehsif ahsiM
.thgilnoom etaciled eht gnitcelfer reuqcal eht ,eceip eht gnirimda ,don I
raW taerG eht derudne taht
,drawroF gnioG yldloB
.wocsoM morf dehctef elcycrotom ym gnivah fo ytrebil eht koot I“
.namecilop a fo esiug eht otni gnippets erofeb
.ybbol eht hcaer ew litnu
.sdees kcalb htiw delkceps hself hsietihw mrif gnilaever
retoocs eht tops ew ,daeha pU
.dehcneuqnu seog tsriht on gnirusne
.dnah thgir ym ni etteragic tilnu eht htiw gnitegdif ,elkcuhc I
.knird sih nwod stes ahsiM
,mih ediseb regit eht htiw noitasrevnoc a pu sekirts eH
,lortnoc tropssap rof enil eht ni redro si ereht elihW
,em dnuora mra gnorts a sparw ahsiM
”?drib elttil ,deifsitas uoy erA ?oS“
waP .drawkcab pets suoituac a ekat I
.ynohpocac wobniar a otni noitcelfer eht gnitrotsid
.ruf nworb ymaerc sih stnemelpmoc roloc eht tub
,ssik etanoitceffa na mih evig I ”?os taht sI“
,tuoba zzihw sretoocs derewop-maets ,teerts eht nI
.ecnaraeppa tuc-naelc a em evig ot tserc ym srevoc pac deppot-talf eht elihw
”?mmH“         ”.flesti tellaw eht tuoba saw reven ssertsid ym tuB .lufituaeb s’tI“
.ytic noen eht ta tuo erats dna reeb tfard hserf a pis I         ***         .tuZ
.tixe eht ot yltcerid daeh ew
.rekaepsduol eht no eciov a secnuonna
.sthguoht eldi ym gnitpursid
setraC“         ”? ixat nu xuev uT ? ixaT ? ixaT“
.spohs roolf-dnuorg fo seraw eht elpmas ot snairtsedep gnitpmet egangis noen gnirekcilf htiw
.wap sih ni ylthgit dehctulc tellaw ym
”,taht ot knird ll’I“
.secamirg dna pis a sekat eH
,staerter eh sa em ta seninac dewolley sih serab drapoel A
htiw dellif lanac lartnec a
.retrauQ hcnerF dna reviR deR eht morf yawa
wap tfel reh ni hcnarb evilo ehT
”,noitazilivic fo sraey dnasuoht-eno fo
.redduhs I sa enips ym nwod stoohs
.rood eht sdrawot serutseg ahsiM
,hsilgnE ni su steerg eh ,ylegnartS
.egdirbyks eht morf krabmesid ot eueuq sregnessap sa gniliar emorhc thgirb eht tsniaga knilc swalc yM .rettum I
”!ecaep ni em evael dna yawa oG .htnom siht emit driht eht si sihT
,emit emos ni denaelc neeb t’nsah hsalpskcab derorrim ehT
sfitarocéD strA eht ni detcurtsnoc
”?letoh eht ot gnitteg ew era woH
.tellaw on tuoba gnihton wonk I“
.ksed lleb eht ta lwob a morf dehcnip ydnac drah ytiurf no kcus ew sa
”.sioegruob uoy t’nera lleW“
.ecnawolla levart suoreneg a teg I taht raey yreve ton si tI“
.gniliar eht tsniaga gniknilc stoob rehtael-tnetap yvaeh sih
,dnuora sleehw enilef eht tub
”.aedi na em sevig tahT
”?og ew llahS ?lleW“
,raW taerG eht morf werdhtiw skivehsloB emit eht yb tub ,tsrif ta yenom fo tol a tsol I“ .skrims eH
.retsyo ruoy s’dlrow eht dna
krop eb ot tuo snrut yletanutrof elddim eht ni étâp ehT
.tneirO riA htiw gnilevart rof uoy knahT“
.tnemtraped noitalusni larutan eht ni egatnavdasid a si yaj eulb a gnieB
,roolf eht no mehyam eht hguorht evaew
,sreerac hctiws ot tnaw reve uoy fI
.lanimirc a fo ssensselkcer lacipyt eht htiw ciffart hguorht gnivaew
,tegrof t’noD“ .elkcuhc a htiw yas I
.nihtiw stuobaerehw sih revocsid ot elba eb dluohs ew
seigolohtna dna skoobnoc suoremun ni dehsilbup neeb evah skrow esohw xof citcra na s’eH
liatkcoc ym ffo hsilop I
steerts eht gnignorht snortap htiw ,gnuoy si thgin eht dna yawa skcolb wef a tsuj si tekraM ehT
,llah eht ot rood eht nepo I
”.ruot part-tsiruot dennac yna naht nuf erom saw siht kniht I ,wonk uoY !deednI“
.gninnips yldi llits leehw raer eht
,egnuol gnikoms eht fo rood eht nepo I
,esuap fo tnemom a tuohtiW
.meht gnitarapes staob nedoow nedal-ylivaeh
”.ecrof eht no gninepo na uoy dnif dluoc I erus m’I
.teerts eht gnissorc sadnap desserd-llew fo puorg a revo gniwolp gnidiova ylworran
.elttab oga-gnol a fo kram eht
,neerg htiw tiurf hsiknip a em sreffo ahsiM ”-ereH
saw sihTDNE EHT
stah deppot-talf ,gnihctam dna snottub ssarb thgirb htiw stekcaj mrofinu owT .suolucidir dna
”!mih no swalc emos sah yttik ehT !tuo hctaW
.rethgif decneirepxe erom eht si ahsiM ,revewoH
.tnemtrapa ym ta neve
:gnimialcorp ylduorp
.seiceps evitcnitsid a fo saw feiht ehT
,rodnev klawedis a morf im nhab a syub ahsiM
.elzzum s’tar tseraen eht no sreksihw eht tnuoc nac I taht worran os si
.eseht fo llats eritne na saw erehT
:yojne esaelP   .ytiniffAruF no
.ếuH ot niart thginrevo eht no stekcit ssalc-tsrif dekoob ev’I“
.ionaH fo dnuorgrednu lanimirc eht htiw tcatnoc ekam tsrif tsum eW“
.srehtaef keehc ym nwod elkcirt retaw fo steluvir sa
.ylitraeh shgual ahsiM
,ecnelupo seduxe nileppez eht fo roiretni ehT
.meht no gniniag er’eW
.elit elbram eht tsniaga kcilc swalc gnol s’ahsiM
ylprahs desserd era sregnessap wollef ruO
”.tner eht droffa ot ssenisub elbatiforp a od tsum yehT“
.ylevitaicerppa don I
siloportem gniltsub eht ta nwod ezag I
,retoocs s’redneffo eht tuo kcip I ,daehA
”.noitcudorp rammarg fo snaem eht ezies ot noitulover a sdeen yrtnuoc ruoy
,elbanosaer erom sraeppa sllib fo kcats sih ecnO
”,iréhc titep nom ,siaçnarf noM“         ”! tiafrap tse siaçnarf am ,uaesio titeP“          .elzzum eht no kcep ykeehc a mih evig I
.neyugN samohT eno si feiht eht ,evag I noitpircsed eht morF .deedni did I“
.noicipsus hcum oot gnisuora diova ot sreyalp rehto eht ot sgninniw sih fo emos snruter ahsiM
.snrut dna sesuap ahsiM
”.stnec evif ylno saw ti eveileb t’nac I“
.tellaw wen ym ni ecalp lufthgir sti ni ti gnicalp erofeb rorepmE daed-gnol a fo
”!won enim si tellaw tahT“
ygolohtna gnimocpu eht dna
.ecap laicalg a ta gnola speerc ,tluaneR a
.ynagoham tsenif eht htiw delenap era sllaw eht elihw
,esirprus flah ,niap flah fo lwoy a htiW
.plug eno ni tser eht gninwod
.uelBeL rotcepsnI ,evitceted eht era uoY“
,sdnopser ahsiM ”,ertsaip eht ot selbur flah a dna owT“         .deedni eeffoc gnortS
,ecaps elbaliava eht fo tsom llif senihcam tidnab demra-eno fo swoR
,tops I rac elgnis ehT
selttob fo wor eht ta ezag I sa dnoces a gniredro etabed dna
ylpmis desserd s’eH
,srehtaef ym revo retaw selbbird eh
.retsloh gnitiaw eht otni ti tols dna
.ytilibissop htiw dellif
elbram etihw eht fo sbals htiw dehsinif si roiretxe ehT
evlossid seuneva thgiarts-relur eht ,retrauQ dlO eht ot sessap ezag ym sA
,enigne eht fo edis eht no regrahcobrut keels eht enimaxe ot nwod tauqs I
,swap ruo ni depsarg sgabtepraC