,mmM“  ”?od annaw uoy od tahw ,oS“
,gnimoc saw siht wenk I
,derettu I ”...traeh ym ni...yb
.gninrom tsrif eht gnirud sgge dna tsaot ym htiw gnola og ot yart tiurf dexim fo dnik emos em tog eH
”.raey fo emit siht ereht tuo s’tahw onnud uoY
.hcrop eht nwod detnirps eh sa tuhs welf rood ehT
.redluohs ym revo detfird ezag s’ruhtrA
.esolc ni gninael dna kcen ym dnuora dnah derujninu sih gnipparw ,pal ym otno dils eh ,tnatsni na nI
,seye ym desolc I   .teews tub ,tniaf
.wonk uoy tel ot gnillac m’I
.guh eht otni gnieotpit erofeb tnemom a rof detatiseh I  ”.nos ,ay evoL“
,emit tsrif eht roF
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.seirecorg ekil seidal pu gnikcip dna llor ’n‘ kcor gnignis sregdab deciov-peed esoht fo eno saw I ekil
”.oot uoy eerf annog m’I .ydroG ,uoy eerf annog m’I“
,did eh erehw nwod tas I
”.gninrom siht mraf sih hguorht ’nipeerc riap a was eh thguoht eh dias elliviM natS
rood eht no dekconk enoemos nehT
,nezorf ,ereht doots I
.ebor ym fo ffulf eht hguorht debmoc sdnah sih ,ssik eht nI
.denaorg I ”,sraey erom xiS“
,yrujni nwo sih ot tnereffidni ylrettu ,mih denigami I
,elihw a eb ll’tI
,esirnus eht fo seuh eht yb detcartsid flesmih gnidnif neht
.sih ot nruter remmilg etanoissap taht was I
.guh ruo fo tuo su gnikahs
.bmil eht otni kcab noitasnes gnikrow ,wap eht gnilggiw dna pecib eht gnitcartnoc
”.taht esu tsuj dluoc yeht ,elbat eht no doolb bmud ruoy tog uoy fi tuB“
,niaga metsys eht detramstuo eh taht
”.pu demraw uoy teg ll’I dna nehctik eht ni nwod tis tsuj uoY
.nus tresed toh a rednu sisao na erew htuom sih fi sa
,nrow sih nwod dna pu gninnacs ,detatiseh I ”,hA“
tsirw sih fo tsiwt thgils eht koot ti dna
.droG ’lo devlos yllanif eh kniht ot mih detnaw I
”.oot em swonk eh tuB
”?huh ,secnailppa wen rof deticxe gnitteg ydaerla—
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sdrow otni kcab sgnileef eseht tup ot ytiliba eht htiw
,rorrim eht ni elzzum ym gnikcehc ylkciuq ,mih dniheb yawllah eht nwod yaw ym delbma I
,edis ym no yldrawkwa gnipeels saw I :serugiF
,hguohT .yab eht yb nwot
”...thgilnus gnisir fo sllih revo gnihcterts
.reilrae tuo ekorb setamni eerhT“ .em derongi eH
”.noos lla ti gnivael eb ll’ew emahs a s’tI“
.mih teerg ot nosirp eht ot nwod evird ot kniht neve dluoc I erofeb emoh ym ta em gnisirprus
.eciov euqsurb sih ni detnurg daD ”,nos ,yeH“
,dias I ”,daD ,uoy evol I“
.lla retfa elytsefil ’stnerap ym htiw nommoc ni gniht eno dah I sseug I
tnemom eht gniruovas
.delbmurg eh ”?thgir ,nosaer on...mmM“
”.srewolf eht rof sknaht dnA .oot uoy evoL“
,nwod yats ot ruf ym dna neve yats ot eciov ym gnicrof ,derewsna I ”,haN“
.nuh ,eeffoc eht rof sknahT“
.enihcam eht ot kcab gnitfird
.teop a fo ecnagele eht htiw ekops dna em ot kcab daeh sih detfihs eH
.tnemeerga delbmum eh sa edis-
.ecnalg a em gniraps tuohtiw taes s’revird eht otni gnibmilc dna rood eht nepo gnillup
.ni em gninokceb yldetcepxenu
.elzzum sih fo srenroc eht ta dellup nworf A
dlo er’ew snaem taht fi rednow I“
.niaga tuc eht gnitcepsni ,htolc eht devomer eH
.yldi deggurhs I os
.knird dehsinif-flah s’ruhtrA ta nwod gnirats
.rood eht degnab skconk erom eerht
,daetsni no sthgil gniliec eht dekcilf I
ym ni espal a ekil ,tniop siht ta ylidaets esir ot demees hcihw
.sregnif sih htiw kcab ym debbur eh sa em dnuora denethgit mra siH
,noisacco no senob ym otni gnipeerc ega eht tlef I
,deksa I ”?eeffoc tnaw uoY“
.pis artxe na retfa yawyna esor I ”.haey
.enoyna dellik reven eH“
ytidigirf emos htiw detnurg eh ”,eniF“
eht ot kcab yaw rieht edam yeht erofeb pohs ym otni gnillup srac ni tuo detnuoc
,enim rednu ecalp otni dils smra siH
.daor tlahpsa deggur eht htiw detcesretni tnemevap eht erehw ot gnidecer ,yawevird eht no dnuora gninrut ,gnivom saw rac eht ,tnatsni na nI
htuom sih ot gum eht esor ylidaets ruhtrA
.esav eht otni kcab pils ti tel I erofeb ffihw tsal eno koot dna
.gniniats dnim t’ndid I gnihtemos rof deruocs dna nehctik eht fo edistuo tesolc nenil eht ot edorts I
.reverof eb t’now ti tub
.denetfos ezag siH
”?dnah ruoy pu dekcuf uoy woh tahT
.tuhs desserp ti sa kcol eht gnittes
.kcab riahc eht degdun dna pu doots eH
?enoyna ees t’ndid uoy erus uoY“
.ebor ym deiduts seye nworb siH  ”.daD ,yeH“  .ecaf-
.htolc eht htiw htuom sih depiw dna nwod gum eht tes eH
.llef sevael tsrif eht emit eht dnuora thgir
.nway nautnagrag a htiw dlrow eht koohs dna elzzum ym nepo tohs I erofeb daeh ym evoba meht esor dna wap rehto ym htiw ti tem I
.mih rof tnenitnoc eht ssorca nur dluow I ,srehto no
.deniatniam yldrah I ssarg otno nwod gnitfird ,yllanoisacco llef
”ytpmE taeS enO“ saw sihT
,dezingocer I raeb a :spoc rehto owt htiw ,tnemevap eht no pu dellup
.suoivbo gnihton gnidnif dna skcart sih rof gniruocs
pis evitatnet tsrif sih ni
,yawyna tneicna saw ti derugif I tub ,flesym ti dexif ev’dluoc ylbaborP
,tnaillirb fo evaw A
,tiuspmuj sih fo snihs eht gniytrid
ruhtrA gninigami
ot-ecaf mih tem dna rood neercs eht nepo dils I
.ebor ym fo redluohs eht otni ffins suoirobal ,peed a koot eH
.denruter eciov yrehtils sih erofeb
”.gnideelb er’uoy ,nuh ,tiaW“
,”elyts yob dab s05“
.naem ahctahw wonk I ,haN“ .elims erar a dekcarc eh ,ylnedduS  ”…hu—I“
,yawa dekcilf ecnalg sih
.edaced-flah tsap eht rof sesserttam hcni-elgnis no gnipeels fo derit werg eh erus m’I
,mih fo kniht em edam tI
,meht fo nuf ekam ot devol ruhtrA
.lewot elbatius a dekcip I sa
kramedart sih revo ragus fo slufnoops luferac tuo gnirusaem dna sknird ruo gniruop erofeb llaw a hguorht detrad evah llew sa thgim I
.em tuoba tihs od t’ndluow yehT“ .deddon eH
,hguoht ,htnom siht ni gnihtemos saw erehT
.htrof dna kcab gnikcilf liat
em dlot syawla ruhtrA
.t’ndid I ekil ti derewsna I—dezingocer I
.sregnif gnol sih htiw elbat eht gnippat dna nwod knird sih gnittes ,desum eh
.don etanoissapmoc a otni denrut
,taorht sih deraelc ruhtrA
,rood tnorf eht ot yaw evag ti sa sriats eht nwod ti dewollof I erehw ,yawllah eht otni tuo em del
;syad emos ,tuo ruf ym gnippir ekil leef em edam eH
.dnuora gnihsur ,delworg I ”!ereht thgir eB“
terreFekuD emanresu eht ro
,sdnilb eht hguorht gniretlif nus gniwaht eht dnif ot seye ym denepo I
.rekaeps enohp eht morf yawa delworg evitelpxe na thguac I ,ecnelis gninruter eht nI
.mmM“  ”?wonk’y ,sdnekeew no pu teg ot draH“
.em revo sehcni elpuoc a doots llits eh hguoht
.mih ot kcab denrut I sa
.esuoh eht otni kcab delpmart dna yawa detsiwt neht
.deb fo tuo deppord I sa degniwt seenk yM
”.tniopefink ta uoy dleh I yas tsuj ,ereh tnecs ym sllems enoyna fI
tnemegnarra ruo ot tsol emit eht ekil
,erew yeht erehw yltcaxe kcab meht gnicalp dna sessalg ruo gnihsaw
”.oga htnom a ti tog ,puY“
.heH“ .dedaf ylkciuq ti erofeb
.niaga kcab tis dna
.ti eldarc ot swap htob thguorb I sa
.krims suopmop a otni denrut nirg siH
”.elbirret s’tahT“
”.aes eht raen sessorc eh fi ffo era steb lla dna
rebmun a ta gnikeep dna retnuoc eht revo gninael erofeb enohp eht ot deretnuas I
.ecnaraeppa tnedifnoc-fles ,looc yllamron sih revo tnemeticxe ekildlihc ,erar a htiw ,deye-ediw
.elddim eht ni snemats eht gnitcetorp
,ylluferac em gnihctaw
”,sallef ,ereh dnuora eno oN .epoN“
”.ay ’nisaet tsuj m’I
.su neewteb gnuh ecneliS  ”.eruS
.cinap ni dekcilf srae yM
.ruhtrA ot tsesolc taes eht gnikat ,nwod meht tes yletaciled dna elbat eht ot htob deirrac I ,dehsinif I nehW
,daor devap-ylesraps fo selim evlewt gnola klaw
.ruhtrA fo tnecs tniaf eht htiw yawrood eht ni ereht gnidnats saw I litnu
.epacse s’esle enoemos rof yaw eht devap evah d’eh taht gniwonk...em
.nwod tam mra ym no ruf eht tlef I erofeb
,tas I erehw gnittis mih tuoba thguoht I
thgiE .nehctik eht ni ti kcuts I dna ,ti riaper dluoc I fi em ot ti dereffo yehT
sevaeL .srewolf dekcip ylhserf emos htiw esuoh eht ot kcab gnitaerter ruhtrA gninigami
,rae ym tsniaga derepsihw eh
.srehto eht morf yawa
.kool suoires a htiw em dexifsnart neht ,daeh sih koohs eh
”?gniod tsirw s’moM s’woh...hu
.eerf og annog m’I
.rac eht otni dekcud eh erofeb evaw lausac a em evag raeb eht hguoht
,esuoh ym raen tserof eht hguorht ylmlac gnillorts
,eno lanoitome yldrawtuo
,yas ot tahw wonk yllaer t’ndid I
.rood neercs detten eht dniheb
.od d’eh tahw wonk I dna ,dad ruoy wonk I“
.depeeb enihcam eeffoc eht nehw
,ssik eht dleh eH
!ot evol d’I ,ahA“
”?huh ,seod reven tI“
,elzzum depirts ym fo ruf gnitsartnoc ylprahs eht hguorht gnireep
srewolf knip fo mlap a tuo gnidloh dna nirg dwerhs a gniraew
”.taert elttil a sevlesruo evig ot detnaw I dna
.tnemom eht ni kcab em dekop retsaot eht fo pop ehT
.nwod smoor elpuoc a enihcam gnihsaw eht otni ti gnitisoped dna gar dedracsid sih gnibbarg
”.uoy kcuF .trA ,dog ym hO“
.ruhtrA ot ti denrut I sa neve ecaf ym peek ot gniyrt
”.rehtie ,gnihtyna od t’ndid I dnA
”…ereh em sdnif eh fi“
.pu saw tahw wenk eH
.kool luftsiw yllufyalp a gniraew
”,yltnatropmi erom tuB
kcolc rehtafdnarg dlo ’stnerap ym ta ecnalg dekcinap A
.ssalg detsorf hguorht derucsbo ruf etihw-dna-kcalb dezingocer
...em ees ot emit ni ti ekam d’eh taht gniwonk
tnemetats taht hguorht derop I
rood draykcab eht morf thgil gniksam niatruc eht ta yaw rehto eht dekool eH
”.elbat eht no srewolf emos evah ydaerla d’uoy derugif I“
.retnuoc eht no talf ti deppord dna enohp eht ffo dekcilc I
.pil eht revo gnisir maets tniaf eht hguorht welb dna
:s’ruhtrA revo tnecs sti deciton I
”.tib a ni tpels...haey
.rorrim eht ot yaw ym delffuhs dna smeti gnidneffo eht no tup ylsselemahs I
.ebordeb ydnugrub tsedom ym htiw dehsalc yeht woh gnisaet
.dnoces tilps a rof feihcsim rieht tsol seye siH ”.tiaw
erom eht neeb ev’thgim I
”.uoy fo htob evol I“
.dewollaws I  ”.uoy evoL“
.t’ndid I esroh a dna
”.ahcteg ll’taht eriw debrab eht syawla s’tI
elbat eht ot nwod dekcilf hcihw
:ecaf nailitper daorb sih no kool eht ees ot tsuj hguorhtkaerb a saw ti ekil dedneterp I
.rehto hcae ot derepsihw dna em ta kcab derats ohw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,derettum ruhtrA ”,dad ruoY“
,mmM“  ”…depleh uoy ecnedive dah yeht fi tub
.deremmilg sesiri kcalb dettils siH
.em deppirg noitome fo evaw a sa seye ym desolc I .evitalpmetnoc
”,tiuspmuj suonieh siht ecalper ot gnihtemos yub
.gninrom siht sknub rieht morf gnissim erew yeht tub ,evael me‘ ees t’ndid eW“
.htuom sih ot pu gum eht dniheb dih yeht erofeb em ot pu kcab dna
,seert eht fo yaws gnihtoos eht dehctaw tsuj dna elihw a rof rood eht ta doots I
yb-edis meht gningila dna sgum owt gnibbarg ydaerla saw I
,gum ym gniniard dna elbat eht ot kcab gniklaw erofeb
.kool kcab-debmoc
.gnilkcuhc flesym dnuof I
.eye ym thguac seinoep fo raj eht litnu ,nehctik eht ssorca gnirats ,gnitiaw tsuj
,nehctik eht ot ti edam I emit eht yB
.kcab dereep dna deppots eh litnu
.selacs sih hguorht yllanogaid nar hsag wollahs A
.seye ym desolc dna kcab sih otni wap ym desserp I
,mih dniheb rac ecilop a saw erehT
”.revo gnimoc er’eW“ .desraeher eh
.daeha retnuoc nehctik eht ot daeh sih denilcni eH
”!skrow eriw debrab woh adnik s’taht ,haeY“
,thguoht fo ssenknalb eht hguorhT
.eciov sih deretne lworg wol a dna ,desuap eH
.etib tsal eht ffo hsinif ot dehsur I sa ruf elzzum ym otni deppird rettub ehT
,tuo gnikeep stib ynnuf yna evah t’ndid I erus ekam ot ebor ym gnitsujda ,sreppils bmud ym ni yawllah eht hguorht yaw ym delffuhs I sA
”.nosirp ruo morf stiftuo rof deleep seye ruoy peeK
”.yllaer ,dab taht ton s’tI
”,yad emos doog rof ereht fo tuo ti ekam ll’I“   .dehgis neht
,tnorf pu ti deit dna tsehc erab ym revo ebor eht deppils I
,tropria eht yb egnar niatnuom tseraen eht bmilc tsuj
.sarelcs wolley revo yletanoitceffa gniworran sdileye
,edistuo kool esolc tsal eno koot I ,em tsap deklaw eh sA
.sregnif sih neewteb seinoep eht gninnips ,elbat gninid eht fo riahc raf eht ni detaes saw ruhtrA
”…ereh yaw ym gnidnif
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.potsdaor ygdots siht ta flesruoy dnif hguone noos d’uoy dna ,dnalmraf emos hguorht tuc
.shtuom ruo tcennoc ot kcab sdaeh ruo dils eW
”.keerc eht dessorc yeht fi eulc oN
retirw noitcif strops dna ecnamor reeuq a
,nwod tas dna elbat eht ot kcab degdurt I
!taerg s’taht ,hO“  ”.tsac eht ni tfel skeew ruof tog ylnO
,seert deyd-egnaro ehT“
;cirbaf eht hguorht selcsum kcab gnorts sih tlef I hguoht
.ti edih dluoc I fi gnirednow saw I .ti nmaD“
.em tih aedi na sa dnoces a rof deppots I ”—I ,oN
.tuo emac dnuos oN
.hguoht ,oot ,no ti gnittup neeb ev’thgim eH
”?taht wonk yeht dluow yhW“
,seye ym denepo I nehW
”…gnihtyna htiw em thguac yeht fI“
,terreFekuD yb ”ytpmE taeS enO“
.ssendedraug sih fo emos tsol eciov sih erofeb ffo deliart eH
.ni srewolf eht tup dluoc eh os nwod ti tes dna elbat eht ot yaw ym edam I ,yawflah dellif raj eht htiW
.kcolc rehtafdnarg eht fo gnikcit eht htiw enola saw I ,won rof tuB
wap ym ni ynoep eht detsiwt I
,tfel ym tem wap thgir yM
.aera eht detuocs eW“
?nwot morf yawa ffo nekorb ev’dluow yeht kniht uoy t’nod“
.tihs od t’ndid eH
.liart s’neK revoc ot ffo tilps eW
.ruoh eht fo nrut eht litnu pu thgiR
.dnah rehto sih htiw niatruc eht edisa gnillup
.doog gniod s’adliH ,hO“
,wollip ytpme eht tuoba thguoht llits I
ereh dnuora poons ot esnes attol elohw a ekam t’nseoD
.guh a ni mih gnihsurc ydaerla saw I
,tib a...gnignevacs...tnew I“
.dnahrednu mih ot ti dessot I
.)ynnuf saw ti thguoht tsuj eh ,sdik yna evah t’ndid ew( gum
.yadot nedraV dna htenneK htiw ereht fo tuo ekorb I“
,dnah doog sih htiw devaw
,em ot gnihtyna od t’ndluow yeht“
I sa dewols ti rewsna ot klaw ksirb yM
aedi elpmis eht htiw deifsitas
.rood eht no dednuop skconk eerht
”.trA ,egnahc reveN“
”.laid deeps no uoy tog ev’I wonk yeht fi yllaicepse—
,nehctik eht fo yawrood eht ot gnillortS
.skconk eerht rehtonA
.ylteiuq ,dias eh ”,droG ,oot uoY“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,guh thgit rehtona ni tem eW
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,terreFekuD yb
.edisni mih dellup I dna
,ekudnikood@ eldnah rettiwT eht yb krow sih wollof yam enO
,seye ym desolc dna sih ot elzzum ym desserp I
”!yrasrevinna yppaH“
.gninrom siht pu ekow I nehw bmun saw mra yM  terreFekuD yb
”.ereht ni gnaH“
”,droG ,oot uoy evol I“
,elzzum ym tsniaga desserp dna
,tuo dellup llits ,riahc sih ot dnuora tperc I erehw
”.drazil eht s’meht fo enO“
,ylregnig dewollaws eH
.dliw eht otni kcab pets tsrif sih erofeb em ta kcab decnalg neht
semihc s’kcolc rehtafdnarg eht fo gninord evititeper ,llud ehT
drawrof degde htuom sih erofeb seye s’rehto hcae tem yltnelis eW
,taht ekil deyats eW
”.pohs eht ni kcehc nac I hguoht ,em no stnemecalper yna evah t’nod I ,oN“
,pal ym fo ffo deppets eH
”,reward eht rof gnihtemos barg dluoc I ereht nwod m’I emit txeN
”?flesruoy rof taht lla dewerb uoY“
”,rof emit evah ew hcum ton
”.emoh a yub ot esohc ew ecalp a fo ecin woh tuoba gnikniht saw I“
.ekahsdnah citnamor ,gnol
”—hu ,emos uoy tog I .hguE“
.taf gnitteg er’uoy rednow oN“
.tnemirted s’nosirp eht ot hcum ,ecnetnes a denesrow reven gnipacsE
,spets eht nwod dettort eh sa
,tnecs sih ni gnikat
.elims railimaf a otni devruc htuom sih fo srenroc ehT
,ylsuoirafen lla detaicnune I
,riahc sih ni yzoc ,ruhtrA gnittis yltaen a revo dezag I
.segnih sti fo ffo rood eht deppir yllacitcarp I nehT
trapa ekorb ew erofeb ,retfos fi
”.lortnoc rednu dnabsuh ym peek t’naC
,rac eht fo tnorf eht ot yaw eht lla deztlaw eH
.yltnalahcnon ta dehctarcs I hcihw ,mra ym gnola deltsirb ruf yM
.retfa muucav nac I“
,tnuoma lausu eht rof werb ot ti tes I
.deggurhs dna pu ti depoocs ruhtrA
egdelwonk eht htiw ti gnihsiler
,hU“  ”?deb fo tuo teg tsuj...uoY“
.pis rehtona koot eh sa mih ediseb riahc eht ot kcab yaw ym edam I
.erehwemos evom annog er’ew dna“
.gnir ym htiw gnilddif flesym dnuof I dna
.mmM“  ”.emoh teg uoy nehw reh evol I reh lleT
.ni tuc eciov ffurg a
,ezeerb a fo hsur eht ot
,srewolf eht fo eno ta deyot wap yM
.rebotcO ni od ot hcum reven saw erehT
.rehtegot tnemom a ni eerf
raj eht pu kcip ot drawrof denael I
.ti gnippirg tnemtnioppasid eht dniheb thgit dekcol
,taoc egnaro lausu sih ni doots drazil mils a ,erehT
.pat eht rednu ti gnittes dna elbaliava raj tsrif eht tuo gnihsif
,neercs kcalb eht ni noitcelfer ym deiduts I
.nirg yhtoot suoitcefni na otni werg elims siH
,moor eht ssorca seye s’ruhtrA tem I
,yllufthguoht mih dehctaw I
,deralced eh ”,yaw eht yB“
.dnats ot em rof dnah a tuo dleh neht
taehw fo saes nedlog eht
.htuom ym otni ti demmarc I erofeb ti rettub ot etunim a em koot tI
,pu taht gninaelc fo lufdnim saw I
:teews em edam tahw fo trap saw taht
.lworg a sa denruter eciov siH
.em htiw tuo gnibmilc llits dna thguac gnitteg uoy enigami t’nac I
”?hguoht ,enihcam eeffoc weN“
dna gnippohs tuo og ebyam ,teffub hcnurb emos yb pots ,nwot otni daeh ot evol d’I“
.htron pu troser iks a nwod em koot ruhtrA
.egnahc t’ndid kool llud siH
,mih ta ylwols deffins I
.rehto hcae fo derit gniworg reve morf su tpek
,redrob nretsae eht ta gnitiaw s’rethguad siH
,ylwols tuo dehtaerb eh
.sredluohs s’rehto hcae no gninael
.raey hcae mih rof stfig yadhtrib dna samtsirhC fo hsats ym tuoba gniklat did syawla I ekil
,em nihtiw peed tirips gnuoy a tey
.rood tesolc eht ta riap knip yffulf eht dettops I litnu sreppils ym rof dnuora deruocs I
,desserd teg ot sriats eht pu yawflah tperc dna pu dehsinif I sA
.pu gnitca saw eno dlO“
,raey yreve gnirrucco
.yrd tnew htuom ym tub
retnuoc eht ot delbmarcs I tub
,tnemom rehtona rof guh eht dleh eh ,yawa kaerb ot ydaer saw I nehW
,kcen ym no ruf eht gniltsur
,yldednim-tnesba ,dnuos eht dewollof I
.llams dna egral ,secifircas eht
,mraf s’elliviM .rM hguorht tuoba gnikcilorf saw I sA“
.krow tseb ym t’nsaW .haeY“
.detcepxe ev’dluoc reve I naht rediw elims em edam ffocs siH
.ti dezeeuqs dna wap ym dnuof eh nehw dloc tlef dnah siH
,sih fo eciov yllevarg ,hcir
rood eht dekcolnu eH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.seinoep emos uoy dekcip I dna
.mmM“  ”!ti bmilc ot em tnaw t’ndid yeht fi ecnef a tliub ev’t’ndluohs yeht ,lleW“
.yrdnual ekil etsat gnihtyreve edam tsuj gninrom eht tuoba gnihtemoS .tsaot fo ecils a was I yaw emas eht stsafkaerb letoh yug hcir ycnaf esoht ta dekool I
.thgiew dnuop-ytriht a ekil enohp eht gnippirg
.nwo ym no krow taht lla od t’ndluoc I tub ,elihw a ni ecno yreve enoemos erih d’I ,eruS
,mra ym dehcterts dna pu tas I
fo dnik emos saw ti ekil dnah sih ot gnulc I ”!yeh—I“  ”.taf
”.redrah yrt d’yeht ,em pots ot detnaw yeht fI .nwot siht ni tnaw I sa hcum sa epacse nac I
.edis sih dnoyeb tsuj ,esav tfihsekam eht fo tuo gnikeep
...mmM“  .rac sih ot dekool I sa rehto hcae tsniaga swap ym deppat I
,yawa klaw dna rood eht esolc ot tuoba saw eh ekil eldnah eht gnipsarg ,denrut eH
,ezeerb gnilrihw eht morf yawa
,esroh dna raeb eht ta redluohs sih revo detniuqs I elihw ylmrif em gnihctulc ,enim rednu dils smra yfeeb siH
sa retnab ruo gnitlah
,swap ym ni hguor tlef tiuspmuj ehT
”.ecnahc eht uoy nevig I dah ,dluow uoy erus m’I .detoN“ .dekrims I
”?thgin tsal daehrevo erew stenalp hcihw wonk uoY
,sroodni kcab saw I ,tnemom kciuq a nI
.rehtegot hguorht erons ot desu ew sessalc eht dna
.noitome on deyarteb ecaf siH ”.hcruhc rof toN
.mih ot gnulc I sa ssik a ni em gnidloh
”—otuA s’nnylF si sihT !olleH“
,yawa dekcilf seye kcalb lacitsym s’ruhtrA
:drah t’nsaw ti ,toof no ereh teg ot detnaw uoy fi
kool lacitylana siH
...ym tsniaga elzzum sih gniddorp
taht ti evig ot rufdaeh krad ym hguorht walc a gnikar erofeb
,ylwols ,ni dehtaerb I
,wolloh elttil ruo ni keew revo dehcterts keeW
.sbir ym hguorht depmuht traeh yM
,mih dewollof spoc owt rehto ehT
.rehto hcae ta derats dna
.tsafkaerb no tup ot tfel dna
,I .me‘ rof tuo eye na peek ll’I“
.daeh sih ni yrteop gnisopmoc
;thgin tsal tserof eht ni tuo saw I ,hO“
.desiar sworbeye sih fo enO
,em dniheb retnuoc eht morf gnizzub detrats enohp yM
.ylesolc ti tcepsni ot tuo ti dekcip I litnu
,rood doow eht esolc ot denrut I ,gnola edorts eh sA
?tahW ?mH“  ”?gninrom siht ereh pu wohs ot neppah sremotsuc suoicipsus yna diD“
.leef dluoc ti ylenol woh dna
.yug tsafkaerb a yllaer t’nsaw I tub ,sgninrom devol syawla I
.stnuocca aidem laicos yrruf sih no ylhtnom seirots trohs sdaolpu ohw
tuhs gniws rood neercs eht tel I
?niaga tuo debmilc uoY“
.wollip rehto eht revo depard mra thgir ym dna sserttam eht ssorca yllanogaid daerps sgel
.tnatsni na ni em morf yawa denrut dna
.sraet fo gninraw eht htiw gninetsilg ylneddus ,em ot pu dils seye siH
.rood eht tuo deppets neht ,elims erom eno evag eH
”?no oidar ruoy evah uoy ,droG“
.loohcs hgih ecnis no krow mih gnihctaw neeb d’I tes emas eht
.hgis a htiw nwod gum eht tes neht
.enilpicsid-fles decitcarp—taolg ot ton—
.ydroG ,mih eerf annog er’eW
.elzzum ym denepo I
teprac yerg ehT
,secnef nedoow ytekcir eht
,trapa ekorb ew sA
.mih hctac annog t’nera yehT
,eveels sih htiw seye sih depiw eh
,degagne tog ew erofeb emit eno rebmemer I
.enihcam eeffoc yloh eht ot thgiarts em koot deb morf egamirglip taerg ehT
,nehctik eht ot kcab tog I nehW
...yb pord d’uoy wenk I
,ylkciuq kcab decnalg eH
,elbat eht ot deunitnoc edirts yM
,ylkciuq ,og tel eH
”!gninrom rep spuc ruof knird uoy sa gnol sa ton tsael tA
,seohs kcalb deffucs sih ot sehtolc deniats-trid
.htiw ruf ym hguorht epiw ot gnihtyna barg ot
.oga sraey wef a ekorb ti—
,nehctik eht hguorht dednuos
.rood draykcab deniatruc eht ediseb radnelac eht ot revo dellorts I ,no eeffoc eht htiW
.nehctik eht fo esnapxe rediw eht ot lellarap
etad delcric eht morf seye ym dils I
.eye eht ni mih kool ot hguone kcab denael dna pirg ym denesool I os ,kcab ym debbur eh
,regdab a ekop ot ruoh na yldrah saw ytriht-
.delims I .esuoh ruO
.ecneserp sih gnihsirehc
.mih dewollof I sa rood draykcab eht ot deppets dna elbat eht no lewot eht deppord eH
,did eh sa em gnisaet
,oN“  ”—em tel ,ereH“
,mets devael-ylesned sti morf esor slatep knip yllirf
,ediw daerps smra siH
,stenibac eht rof enileeb a edam I
,ega htiw retrohs gnitteg neeb d’eH
.teprac moordeb yerg ylggarcs eht hguorht etihw fo sepirts gnol gnicart
”.bmud llits era sreppils ruoy“
,teop eht saw eh tub
.gnihtemos ro ,suoicsnocbus saw tI“
.rehto hcae ot gnulc ew sa ypsar htaerb
.srats eht ees ot gniyrt saw I
”daD tseB s’dlroW“
.meht desolc dna sniatruc eht fo segde eht dnuora swap ym depparw I ,daeh ym fo ekahs a htiW
ym ti dellac ruhtrA
taht ni decnuonna eh
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffA ruF no
.gnivael eb noos d’ti taht
.etihw-dna-kcalb llits—elzzuM
,stsafkaerb troser iks eht dna
.wodniw ssalg detsorf s’rood tnorf eht dniheb epahs esiouqrut a despmilg I litnu reduol tcejbo ot tuoba saw I
.sreciffo rehto eht ot ylmrif deralced eh
.tah s’ffirehs suorcidul dna tekcaj rehtael nworb a ni regdab ykcots a saw edis rehto eht nO
.esuoh ruo dniheb tserof eht otni gnikcud erofeb dray eht ssorca decar
”.emit siht hguone llew krow t’ndiD“
,thgilyad fo kcarc eht ta nwal s’enoemos no gnihcuorc
.nehctik eht ni kcolc eht fo gnikcit eht rof tpecxe ecnelis rettu gnitceted
.nepo ti dekcarc dna rood eht dekcolnu I
.em no kcab gnisucof erofeb ,thguoht a gnirusaem
em ot dnah rehto sih derednerrus eH
”.wed ni lufthgiled dekool yeht thguoht I
,hguoht driew elttil a ti gnidloh saw eH
yawa ekorb ew ,tnemom a retfA
.spar kciuq eerht ni
.tsehc sih no cirbaf egnaro eht ta gnikcip ,derettum eh
.mih revo gnissuf dessim I tub
,dab taht t’nsaw yllaer tI
srewolf knip eht ot detfihs ecnalg yM
.sduolc gnimocni emos drawot decnalg I
”ytpmE taeS enO“   :yojne esaelP
”.esuoh ruoy morf htron gnidaeh spetstoof emos waS
.tuo og ot emit suoregnaD“
.gniog t’nerew seye ym erus ekam ot tsuj ,syad eseht kcehc ot dah syawlA