.afos eht no peelsa llef I tub ,deneppah ti nehw wonk t’nod I
reerac nwo ym htiw mih htiw og t’ndluoc I dna semitemos tol a levart ot dah eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY.goD
.nailuJ htiw derahs I taht tnemtrapa roolf-owt eht ni sriatsnwod dedaeh I
”.kniht I ,peelsa
;sgep detnuom llew morf gnignah erew sgniht fo sdnik llA
.nus eht gnilcric edaced driht rieht deretne yltnecer tsuj dah ohw nem yag owt rof emosdnah erew ew tub ,gnisiarp-fles eb ot toN
.em ot kcab gnimoc saw tI  ”!hO…hO“
.snalp dah enoyreve
?rekool a saw eh uoy llet I diD
.moordeb eht otni nailuJ dewollof I sa dias I
”!pop“ gniyfsitas a tuo evig kcab ym draeh I sa gninaorg ,dehcterts dna tsiaw ym no sdnah ym tup I ,riahc ym morf pu gnidnatS
,yletulosba ,sdneirf erew eW
”…ereh tsud ylbaborp dluohS“
.sdnah ym ni telbat ym htiw afos ym no gnittis
.drawkwa gnihtyreve ekam dluow ti dna ,nuf rieht
.gniod saw eh lleh eht tahw wonk sa hcum sa flesmih lles ot dah eh dna
”?emoh dedaeh xelA“
.sfeirb egnaro-tnrub rengised ,pih sih fo riap a ni ereht gnidnats ,ffo stnap sih dekcik nailuJ
.senot lanoisseforp
,)odeeps a ni did I naht retteb kool did syawla nailuJ(
,oliM sedart-lla-fo-kcaj eht fo edacaf ym niatniam ot gnixat yllatnem saw tI  .tegrof I
,edis ym no gniyl
saw kwahom aneyh erutangis yM
,demahsa saw I esuaceb toN  .yawa dekool I
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb
.hguoht ,moolg-dna-mood os saw gnihtyreve toN
.nuf sih dah ydaerla d’eH
,aremac eht ta gnilims ereht doots eW
renroc eht denrut I   ”!stopS ,em s’tI“
.tsacrevo t’nsaw ti nehw ytic eht fo weiv a fo lleh eno su gnivig ,gnidliub eht ni pu hgih ytterp erew ew ecnis
,now dah I sdrawa ,now dah nailuJ sdrawa ,ssalg muesum gninihs ni seerged ruo
.ti niatniam ot desu eh spaos eht dna ruf sih ot gnignilc llits ssentew eht llems dluoc I
”?yako ,peelsa eb t’nod os ,moordeb eht deen annog er’eW“
.laicos eb ot mih decrof osla boj s’nailuJ
.sdnah ruo ni sknird dna seye ym rednu tniap wobniar fo tib
.elims em edam syawla taht eno saw otohp tsrif ehT
,fo kcart peek ot em rof netfo oot yaw deneppah taht ,em uoy eveileb dnA
nailuJ no sucof tsuj d’I wonk I
,truoc ni now dna deugra dah nailuJ taht esac a
.yllufituaeb os ruf sih dehctam tI
,kcen ym debbur dna pu tas I
,elzzum eht no em dessik dna ni denael nailuJ
.moordeb eht otni mih dewollof dna
”!dnekeew taerg a evaH
dna denway I elihw elttil a hcamots ym dehctarcs I
t’noD“  .trihsrednu dettif eht yb dewollof
.ffo tekcaj sih koot eh sa moor gnivil eht fo edis rehto eht morf dias xelA ”,haey hO“   ”?uoY“
.emosenol ym ni edistuo em gnivael ,desolc rood ehT
.elzzum ym gnivael morf evitelpxe yna tneverp ot
evah ll’I  !ekaJ uoy knaht ,yakO
.sevlehs llams no gnittis ro demarf rehtie
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
aera taht ni troffe hcum neeb t’ndah ereht sraey fo elpuoc tsal eht rof tub
”.ydaer er’uoy nehw deb ot emoc nac uoy os
ti…thgir gnitae ,sthgiew ,snur ,sklaW
”.ylenol leef ot uoy tnaw t’nod I…tsuj I ,haeY“
.emoh yats ot esucxe na dah syawla I esuaceb yltsom—
.rehtegot od dluow evol ni nem owt taht sgniht nuf gniod
.eltrats a htiw pu em gnikaw
.ettelap s’retniap a ekil ruf sih deroloc nailuJ dna
.srenetsil ruo fo lla ton fi tsom ot
,tsuD ot emoC seires eht fo srohtua oc era ohw
eh sa em desaet dneirfyob ym
.aisA dna eporuE ni neve dna yrtnuoc eht revo lla sdneirf dah eh os—
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.semit esoht rebmemer ot detnaw ew
,thgin yadirF a no enola emoh saw I
kcen ym otni delzzun eh sa ylthgirb gnilims
.redlo tog I sa ydobemoh a gnieb ot desu nettog d’I
.yadnoM yb ti no eldnah a teg ot tnaw I
edam dah ew tahw fo llaw a dessap I renroc eht gninruT
.moordeb ym otni dna llah eht nwoD
sraef sih stnorfnoc oliM woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
?mih dessim I taht mih llet I t’ndid yhW
.tuo-teg lla sa emosdnah saw eh tey dna
”?thgin ecin a evah uoy diD“
,laicos tahwemos em tpek nailuJ  .tol a
.larehpirep ym fo tuo spih sih etaryg xelA was I
.drocer deeps dnal a yltcaxe t’nsaw ylrae ruoh na taht toN
.spil eht no kcep a em evag dna em ot pu deppils eH
”evoL fo esaC tuhS dna nepO“   yojne esaelP
.knard eh nehw yllaicepse ,revol hsifles
wef a yletomer krow ot dewolla saw I ,tleb ym rednu ecneirepxe hguone htiW
.detcepxe eb ot saw taht os ,palrevo yllaer t’ndid sreerac ruO
.ksam a ekil ti erow dna elims a decrof I
.cisum sih no gnikrow osla elihw retaeht lacol fo tol a did eh dna ,gnitca neeb syawla dah ybboh s’xelA
derrup eh sa trihs sih rednu pu gnidils
,srevoc eht sgoh eH“
”?thgin eht yats annog t’nsi xelA
.roolf nedoow eht no spetstoof yb dewollof
.drawkwa leef dluow xelA dna
dna yppah erew ew tub ,ytinav t’nsaw tI  .su tuoba lla
erom no koot sotohp ruo ereH
tsel enohp eht revo dlot saw I taht snoitcerroc eht no seton gnikat
gnimmiws ,sekih no gniog ,gnibiv dna gnivil ,tuo gnignaH
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb
.gniklaw s’eh htap eht no peek ot sediced eh fi ro
.em dnuora smra sih depparw dna afos eht dniheb pu emac eh sa dias nailuJ ”,nuh yeH“
”,ylrae elttil a emoh er’uoY“
,deb eht fo edis sih ot klaw nailuJ dehctaw
.tnatropmi si reerac ruoY  .flesym dlot I
.saw eh thguoht I emosdnah woh tsuj sdrow otni tup t’nac I dna ,rekool a saw eH
emoh gnieb tsuj dekil I taht gnizilaer detrats I
evoL fo esaC tuhS dna nepO“
.pihsnoitaler nepo na fo seiradnuob eht detcepser eW
repmah eht otni trihs eht gnissot ,ffo sehtolc nwo ym gnippirts saw I
”.desolc rood tnorf eht nehw pu ekaw t’ndid uoy desirprus m’I
.ffo snaej ym teg ot nwod dna pu gnipmuj dna
rehtegot llew leg yllaer t’ndid I dna xelA tub
.revo gnimoc si xelA“
,gniogtuo erom saw I egelloc nI
.dnabtsiaw sih otni wolf hcamots sih fo sruotnoc eht tel
.nwotnwod rab wen siht ot em koot xelA“   ”!emosewa saw wohS“
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb
”,cisum ni etsat elbirret dah syawla ev’uoY“
”.dnaherofeb em dlot uoY  .wonk I“
.noitcerroc etunim-tsal a eriuqer reve spu-rehgih eht dluohs stide kciuq yna rof yug ot-og eht eb ot sneppah osla ohw dna
decnal thguoht evisserped taht tuB
”?dnats t’nac I dnab taht ,tahW“
.ot detnaw eh fi
.hcamots ym ni gnileef driew a tfel ti ,llitS
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
.noonretfa yadirF ynnus siht ma I erehw si hcihw
————————————  .edam eb ot evah secifircaS
,gnisserdnu tpek dna
.mih ta delims dna sgnileef esoht nwod dehsup I os
syawla dah I dna nailuJ tub
,emit erom etsaw mih ekam ot tnaw t’ndid I
.neffits flesym tlef I fi neve flesym deppots I tub…mih gnisserac
tub rehtona eno htiw detsugsid
.ffo denrut dah sthgil citamotua eht was dna moor eht dnuora dekool I
.gnol oot rof gnittis saw I taht nialpmoc ot demees ydob eritne yM
.egdirf eht ni kcab eciuj fo reniatnoc eht gnittup
railimaf yliraew
.ssecxe elbaviecnoc yreve ot meht tnualf ot
.atouq muminim on si ereht :dias tahT
ot hsiw ton od ohw su fo esoht
,ffo trihs sih gniggut elihw dias eh ”,haeY“
,wobniar a ni detniap
.elbatrofmoc ti dnuof tsuj ew esuaceb
.dlog ni degde partskcoj kcalb a rof evas dekan saw eH
.slaudividni sa su tuoba erom
.tesolc eht morf sehtolc elbatrofmoc erom hcum emos tuo koot
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.gnivom tpek I sa gnilims saw I
a sa keew eht fo syad
.meht dlot I nehw sdaeh s’elpoep ynam revo welf ekoj taht ,haeY
.sesunob gnimocpu rieht tub gnihtyna no eerga ton dluoc yltnerappa srekam-noisiced etaroproc esoht esuaceb
.krow eht no desucof dna
ni em tuoba selcitrA
.wodniw eht ni noitcelfer nwo ym was I dna
.raelc syawla saw rewsna eht tub ,tnemnorivne lufsserts a hcus ni toof pets ot derehtob neve I yhw derednow I semitemoS
.yrtsudni siht ni boj a dnal ot em gniwolla ,pu werg I sa ti derutrun dna tnelat ym was stnerap yM
evag eh ”,mmM“    .sevil laudividni ruo ni no gniog saw tahw tuoba hcum deklat t’ndah ew dna keew ysub a neeb
doog a t’nsaw eh taht toN
.ycavirp meht evig ot dekil I esuaceb tub
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sserP grebztiurF yb dehsilbup
.tsehc ym revo smra ym dessorc dna noitartsurf kcom fo ecaf a edam I
evag neht ,daeh ym fo kcab eht otni delzzun eH
.ti rof daeh a evah ot mees t’ndid I ecnis ,lla ti fo trap
.elims a htiw dias nailuJ ”,oN“
,tsiaw s’nailuJ dnuora saw dnah s’xelA  .lliks taht htiw
.tnew yeht ffo dnA
krow no desucof I oS
,edirP yppaH .stsacdop ruoy
?gniyl I saw yhW  .deil I ”,t’now I“
,mih gnihcuot tuoba thguoht I
;rewohs eht fo tuo hserf saw eh tub…mih detnaw
.flesym dlot I !esicrexe elttil a rof emiT
”.trecnoc taht ot gniog era I dna eH
.gnitarg elttil a eb dluoc eh ,siht ekil knurd saw eh nehw tub ,ti tuoba kcid a t’nsaw eH
dah tI  .saw taht tahw ssecorp ot deirt I  ”…togrof I .hO“
”?rof ylrae emoh emac uoy taht no gniog
?em htiw eb ot mih detnaw I tahT
.nailuJ ta dekool dna denrut I
”…ot emoh emoc ot detnaw tub
derewsna I ”,sknahT“
.pu ti gnimmah tsuj ro ,knurd saw rehtnap ehT
,thgilnus htiw thgila saw nehctik ehT
,reerac ym no desucof dna nailuJ htiw esolc tog I nehw tub
,desserppus yletarebiled neeb evah
,god detniap emosdnah ym emoh democlew dna
.nuf rieht evah meht tel dna tuhs elzzum ym peek tsuj saw od ot dedeen I gniht eht
.su fo edis taht tsol t’nevah ew kniht ot ekil I
.llaw eht no kcolc eht ta dekool I
,wollip a rednu mra ym dekcut dna revo dellor I hgis lanretni na htiW
.yawyna no gnikrow m’I troper siht evah I“
.moordeb eht otni dedaeh eh sa ylwols
,ereht saw reffo eht erus m’I  .meht nioj
.sfeirb ym gniraew tsuj
doof eht deganam nailuJ yllufknahT
.deb eht otni gnikop
”.sleweJ ,oot uoy evoL“
yrellag otohp eht yb deklaw I sa duol tuo dias I
gnihtyna eveileb uoy ekam dluoc xelA
.stifeneb htiw sdneirf ton tub
dna ylleb sih no wol dial yehT
.elzzum eht fo edis eht no dneirfyob ym dessik dna
.eit sih gninesool dna tekcaj tius sih gninottubnu saw ohw
tub yllacol elpoep eht fo wef a degassem I
,nepo zzub rood eht draeh I
.eciuj fo ssalg a flesym deruop dna egdirf eht denepo I ,nehctik eht ta gnivirrA
.redluohs sih revo depard xelA htiw nailuJ emac ni dna
”evoL fo esaC tuhS dna nepO“
.nailuJ ta pu dekool dna denrut I sa hguoht dnim on mih diap I
edisa sthguoht evitagen eht dehsup I
gnicnad emos did eW
”.og ot doog s’ti os ,gnihtyreve dna steehs eht degnahc I
,egelloc morf yob aneyh toh ,enitsirp eht t’nsaw I
,rengised gnimoc-dna-pu na sa senizagam emos
won yb sseltbuod si edirp fo ”noitazilauxes“ tuoba etabed ehT
.moorhtab eht otni deppets eh sa dednopser nailuJ ”,haeY“
.dliub ni redaorb ylthgils mih dna ,delcsum dna nael gnikool em tpek ti tuB
a fo tib a eb dluoc eh dias dah nailuJ dna ,em rof hsarb oot tib a saw eH  .taht ekil
ecitsuj evitarotser fo tub
thgir yreve sah edirP
.supmac eht raen ecalp koot taht tneve edirP a ta rehtona eno tem ohw sdargrednu owt
.rehtona eno dnuora smra ruo
.era yeht ohw fo duorp eb ot thgir hcum sa tsuj evah
.ot noitnetta gniyap neve ton saw I taht oediv ebuTuoY modnar
a htiw ,strohs fo riap a tsuj gniraew dna sseltrihs erew su fo htoB
.kcab srevoc eht gnillup
erofeb diov eht otni detuohs I ”!!timmad doG“
ytilauxes reeuq dna ,seidob reeuq
”?retfa tnemtrapa eht ot kcab emoc ot gniog xelA dna uoY  .enif ,eniF“
.elbat eeffoc eht no nwod telbat eht gnittup
taht dediced I os ,sregnif ym ni licnep a dna sduolc eht ni daeh ym dah syawla ev’I buc a sA
pu denepo rood ehT
og tsuj t’ndid I yhw gnirednow eb thgim uoY
.su fo tuo eno citamsirahc eht syawla saw eH
,I dna nailuJ dewohs tI
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.god detniap laiceps ym htiw em gnirrats
.keew txen yb enod ti
,krow eht no sucof syawlA
.esulcer a emaceb I taht tcejorp tnerruc ym no drah os gnikrow neeb dah I—eno taht rof flesym tub emalb yllaer ot eno on dah I
moordeb retsam dna moor gnivil ,nehctik ruo htiw sriatspu moor tseug a dna eciffo na dah eW
,dewollof I dna deb eht fo edis sih otni dils I
.etaudarg dna dargrednu htob ,sraey egelloc ruo morf stnemom fo yarra na erew sotohp gniwollof ehT
.pu sdnah sih dleh dna dias nailuJ ”!haoW“
.skool esoht fo eno em
.ereht lla saw
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.mraerof s’nailuJ gnola bur ot pu gnimoc dnah ,dias I ”,haeY“
,ediw erew swodniw ehT  .sriatsnwod
dna rehtegot su tuoba ssel erew sotohp ehT
.deew dna lohocla fo dellems eH
hgis gnol a ekat dna
,redluohs ym hcuot dna nwod emoc
?thgir ,stide eht rof ti s’taht dnA“  2 fo 1 traP
.ssob sih htiw sdnah gnikahs rennid ycnaf a ta mih fo otohp a htiw etelpmoc
,evol dna ,evil su fo ynam elihW
.deliat-yhsub dna deye-thgirb os erew segami esoht ni gnilims sdik ehT
,oN  .deifsitasnu dna driew elttil a gnileef su fo htob
.esopmi ot tnaw t’ndid I tub ,gnihtemos denioj dna ni dettub evah dluoc I wenk I
:yletaidemmi hsilbatse su tel ,ytiugibma yna eb ereht tseL
repap ot slliks ym gnittup
,tsitra tpecnoc dna rengised cihparg a sa yrtsudni emag oediv eht ni skrow ohw aneyh dettops a
”.oliM ,uoy evoL“  ”.esruoc fO“
.oga ruoh na tuobA“
.thgil taht ni mih ees t’ndid tsuj I tub ,yal
,retal sruoh eerhT
erew ew esuaceb ton…kcab ot kcab tpels yllausu eW  .em ot saw kcab sih os revo dellor neht dna
.deb ot og s’tel ,stopS ,nom’C“
”?no gniog gniht taht evah I rebmemer uoy
.sevlesruo fo erac ekat ot erus edam
.aedi tsrow eht t’nsaw
peed…tsuj…oN“   ”?maerd daB“
,syaw yranidroartxe dna evissergsnart yletarebiled ni
.kwahom ym dettap dna pin eltneg a rae dnuor ym
,deb ot gniog neht dna gniklat thgin eht dneps ylbaborp dna xes evah t’ndluow eW
yrots s’yadoT dna
---------------------------------------------------—   ”.evol ,sknahT“    ”.nuh yakO“
nosrep dab a reven saw eh tuB
,mrif wal sih ta sutats rentrap eht ot noitomorp sih dna
dnah a tlef I nehw ,telbat eht gnippirg llits sdnah ym
.eb ot stnaw ti sa lauxes sa eb ot
.ynnuf os gnipeels morf ereht ehca eht ta gnicniw
,tuo dellac I ”?ebaB“
flesym gnirongi elihw peels ot gniyrt dna seye ym gnisolc
.meht raeh dluoc I taht hguone duol tog yeht esac ni cisum emos no tup dna
emos deyalp VT eht elihw aidem laicos dna setis swen hguorht dekcilf I
ecnaifed fo ylno ton tca na si ti
,erised reeuq nehW
dna hsur taebtraeh nwo ym tlef I
?ti teg ,ahah ,god detniap a s’eh esuaceB
dna revo depmuls saw I
tius ssenisub sih fo tuo gnitteg
.hgis duol a tuo tel yletaidemmi dna—enohp eht pu gnuh I eybdoog yreehc a htiW
,afos eht morf pu doots dna denway I
s’tahw oS“  .taefed ni pu sdnah ym dleh dna dehgis I ”,wonk I ,wonk I“  ”—erom netsil athguo uoy ,oliM“  .tnaem ti tahw wenk I ;skool nailuJ erutangis eht fo enO
.stengam owt ekil rehtegot nward yltnatsni erew eW
,sthgiew detfil ylsuoires neve eh kniht t’nod I
,eciffo oiduts ym sa moor eraps eht gnisu saw I os ,rekrow dirbyh
,emit doog rieht niur t’ndluoc I  .tliug fo esnes a gnireggirt ,eroc ym otni nwod
llac eht etum dluow I semitnetfO
.shgiht sih ot gniog seirolac eht tuoba yrrow ton dna ekac elohw a tae dluoc eH  .ydob doog a gnipeek ta krow ot deen t’ndid ohw syug esoht fo eno saw xelA
dias eh ”,eciuj egnaro…mM“
,retnec dna tnorf syawla saw yenrotta nA