.ylkciuq oot gniht ’pihsnoitaler nepo‘ siht otni
.elkcuhc a htiw dias I
.oopmahs sih llems dna ydob sih morf taeh eht leef dluoc I  .em tsniaga dehsup saw
.yltsom…ecaps lanosrep ym gnitcepser
?lla ta mih t’nsaw taht yaw a ni
”evoL fo esaC tuhS dna nepO“   yojne esaelP
,mih ot kcab denrut dna dehgis I
.tuoba lla si efil ruoy gnirahs tahw s’taht dna ,lamron s’tahT
.emit eht ta detartsurf saw I tub
.nailuJ morf deohce ,noitartsurf naht rehto noitome na htiw decal emit siht ,lworg A
,taht od uoy tel evah t’ndluow I  .stopS ,koob a ekil uoy daer nac I wonk uoY
.neppah ot dah reve ti fi efil ym ’teser‘ ot emit fo tuo gninnur saw I
dna seenk sih neewteb sdnah sih
I ma yhW  ?siht gniredisnoc neve I ma yhw…tiaW
”—t’ndid I dna rewohs eht fo tuo tog tsuj dah uoy tub ,thgin tsal senob ruoy pmuj ot gniog saw I“
ekat mih tel I
.nwod dna nwod dna
dlrow eht htiw llew saw lla
tub…eborp ,ecitne ,egaruocne ,ni pmuj ot detnaw eh
.sserP grebztiurF yb dehsilbup
”?gniddik uoy erA“   ”?thgir ,em htiw xes evah ot tnaw llits uoY
,reilrae pu teg ot dah eh esuaceb em erofeb deb ni yllausu nailuJ
”.em htiw ffo ti kaerb
dna…esle gnihtyna yrt yllaer t’ndid eW
.sseccus fo seirots eb tsum yeht
,drah yllaer s’taht tub
.selcric gnitrofmoc ,wols ni ti gnibbur dna kcab ym no dnah sih ,dias nailuJ ”,ooooliM“
,noitatnemirepxe egaruocne dna eripsni ot era yeht fI .os ylthgir dna
”.ti tuoba klat s’tel ,lleW“
.krow siht ekam ot segnahc ekam ot deen htob eW“
”.em tuoba yrrow uoy woh ekil tsuj
,yako kool t’nod uoY“
,ylevitalpmetnoc dias I ”,wonk I“
.ylthgils deggurhs dna dekrims I
.detartsurf dna tnetnoc htob saw I
.detartsurf osla saw I
.teiuq deniamer eh tub deworruf worb s’nailuJ  ”…fi…fi od I od…tahW“
.ria eht ni pu ttub
,elucylop eno ,elpuoc eno
,taht ekil tsuj dnA
?dnuora evol I enoemos peek ot tsuj nwod peed tespu yltnatsnoc gnieb htiw evil I dluoC
naht gnikool retteb hcum os era syug eseht dna
.gnikniht no desucof I
.dnim ym raelc ot detpmetta dna ,seye ym desolc ,shtaerb peed wef a koot I
,esolc em dellup dna em dnuora mra sih tup nailuJ ”,erom
,doof suoiciled yllufrednow fo dellems llits ria ehT
pots t’ndluow eW
”,pu pihsnoitaler eht gninepO“   ”…wonk
.moorhtab eht ot tnew dna pu tog ylgnigdurgeb I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.rewsna rehtona dnif rO
.teerts yaw-owt a s’tI  .em htiw gnimoc otni uoy dorp yletinifed ll’I tub
eb ot evah uoy tuB“
.snoitome eht ton ,stcaf eht no desucof dna
,aliov dna ,gnikooc tuoba owt ro gniht a nrael ot emit saw ti derugif I llah eht nwod denrub tsomla I retfA“
.sreerac ruo no desucof emit fo tol a dneps eW“
.siht ekil flesruoy gnirutrot neeb evah t’ndluohs uoy ,aneyh diputs uoY“
pu elzzum ym detfil dna nihc ym rednu deppils dnah A
”.yawyna ,si eh naht ti ta retteb er’uoY
dna llew sa nailuJ rof eno deruop I
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb
,pihsnoitaler eht gninepo ot deerga evah t’ndluow I ,ysuolaej fo elbapac erew uoy thguoht I fi“
,afos depahs-L eht fo trap rehto eht no nwod tas dah nailuJ
.ylevitatnet deksa I ”?yako er’ew ,oS“
.sih ni sdnah ym koot nailuJ
”.od ll’uoy yas uoy tahw ot kcits uoy taht s’ti ,uoy tuoba wonk I gniht eno s’ereht fi esuaceB“
tsenoh eb ot deen od ew tuB“
,nosrep eno rof skrow hcihw gnihtemos taht ron
s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy
deracs os neeb dah I esuaceb tsehc sih ot gnulc I
.sih fo sbro lufituaeb esoht rednu ssenpmad eht htiw neve
llet dluoc I hguoht neve yrp ot gniog t’nsaw eH  .smret ym no tuo ti teg em gnittel saw eH
.ezeeuqs a sregnif ym evig mih tlef I dna ti
.uoy gnitruh si gnihtemos esuaceb pu ecnatsid lanoitome gnittup er’uoy ,su neewteb sgniht tup dna ,taht ekil yawa klaw uoy nehW“
,lufsseccus sa detciped yllausu era seirots ruo ni stnemirepxe ehT
og…tsuj ot tnaw I  .xelA htiw od uoy tahw ekiL
.ecaf ym morf yawa sdnah eht koot dna hgis a htiw dias I ”,oN“
.yllacitahpme erom detaeper dna ,deddon I  ”.lliw I“
?srae eht neewteb em gnissik dna em gnidloh yltnerruc god detniap eht ees ton I did ,senecs esoht lla fo tuo ,yhW
.plug a htiw dias I
”…naem neeb reven s’eh tub ssarc tib a s’eH  ?uoy tlusnI
.spil eht no ,drah ,em dessik dna esolc em dellup eH
uoy no desucof evah dluohs I tub ,neeb evah
.seye sih otni kool ot pu daeh ym detlit dna keehc ym deppuc dnah egral siH
.retsef ti tel t’ndluohs uoy
,ma I naht gniogtuo erom hcum os syawla er’uoy dna ,taht od uoy stel yllausu eludehcs ruoy tuB
.od I naht netfo erom raf dna ,od I naht
?uoy truh xelA diD
.nwod mees tsuj uoY“
gnikst prahs a edam nailuJ tub niaga yawa pets ot deirt I
.sgnileef ym tuoba ’gnibbif‘ yb smelborp dediova semitemos I tub ,elur a sa ,eil t’ndid eW  .em ta deralg eH
,tnemom taht ta gnileef driew a saw tI
.diova ot detnaw I gnihtemos ,tnemrot dna niap mih esuac dluow I yaw rehtie
.elims a otni yawa deleep ylwols hcihw eralg a em gnivig
”.uoy morf taht ekat ot tnaw t’ndid I dna tnetnoc dna yppah mees uoy
?otni nrut sgninrom yadrutaS ylevol eseht dluow tahW
.dnah ym fo kcab eht htiw seye ym gnipiw
enod erew yeht litnu klat nosrep eht tel ew
”?gnissim m’I gnihton s’ereht…ekiL“
.tuo emoc ot gniog ylbaborp saw bos a did I fI  .klat t’ndluoc I
dna nailuJ yb derahs ,dlrow ruo—
tnaw ew taht rehto hcae wohs ot regae erom elttil a eb dna ,nepo erom eb
.yppah enoemos ekam ot tsuj ecifircas t’ndluoc I wenk osla I tub
.etalocohc klim detlem ekil htooms eciov sih dna gnimoclew dna mraw saw tnecs sih
evoL fo esaC tuhS dna nepO“
sih htiw deb eht ni nwod ecaF
.yawa kool ot dah I dna em ta denworf nailuJ
.deddon dna dias I ”,haeY“
.pots em gnikam ,dnuos
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY.goD
”.skcarc eht hguorht pils ot deneppah tsuj sgniht ,rehtar
.won tuo gnimoc lla saw ti dna…deifirret os
”.kcis eb ot gniog er’uoy ekil kool uoY
,ot detrats ew nehw deneppah tahw rebmemer uoY“
,ni emahs on si erehT
,krow lliw deirt gnihtyreve taht eetnaraug on si ereht :dias tahT
.derettups ylkciuq I
;did ew gnihtemos saw tI  .gnihtyna dedda eh erofeb ecaep ym yas em tel ot gniog saw eH
”.mriuqs I nehw ti ekil uoY“
”.moor mrod ruoy ni nemaR ekam ot delggurts uoy nehw rebmemer I
.htaerb deredduhs a tuo tel I dna meht rednu gnimrof sraet leef dluoc I
”,oliM“   .dah syawla eh
”.drawrof troffe tup ot evah uoY
.dne dluow maet eht diarfa saw I“
.taht naht retteb eb ot dah I  .srovaf yna nailuJ ro flesym gniod t’nsaw I yteixna dna noitome evitagen htiw gnippird ti htiw tuo gnihtyreve taps I fi tuB
.pu kcip etar traeh ym edam dna hcamots ym deppirg yteixnA
!melborp a t’nera uoY“  .niaga delworg nailuJ ”!oN“   ”—revol
.efil ruo ,emoh ruo ,tnemtrapa ruo ta dekool dna duol tuo dias I
”,skcirt reywal yna dniheb edih t’now I esimorp I“
.retal emoc dluoc snoitomE
”.oliM ,erew uoy kniht t’ndid I“   ”.gnihtyna ro
,tuo eugnot sih fo pit eht kcuts dna dennirg eH
”.renoos ti ees t’ndid I yrros
”.krow ot siht tnaw htob esuaceb
.ti tuoba suoiruc osla erew uoy dna ,pihsnoitaler eht pu denepo ew nehw ynroh yllaer saw I
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb
ekat ot yrt uoy tuB
nehctik eht morf cisum raeh dluoc I
?yppah em ekam ot tbuod dna yresim ni evil rehtar d’uoy oS“
ton s’ti tub ,nem rehto htiw peels ot ekil s’ti tahw ekil htob ew dna
.erom ecno nwod dekool dna deddon I
,oliM ,gnihtyna od uoy ekam t’nac I“
nwod gnillaf neeb dah I
.ecaf ym nwod gnilkcirt sraet erom ,llits gniyrc saw I
.kcatta cinap a otni em tnes tsomla ,hcum os devol I nam eht gnisol ,nailuJ gnisol fo aedi ehT
.ni gnimoc smaebnus gninrom eht htiw taerg dekool sllaw eht fo gniroloc ehT
,xes erom detnaw I
?sevil ruo htob gniniur
”…siht od t’nod ,sleweJ ,esaelP“
.xes hcum os dah eW
dna…yawyna hcnurC ni syawla t’nera uoY“
,relpmis hcum os saw efil
depparw dna tsehc sih otni daeh ym gnillup
.enut eht ot gnimmuh
!siht od t’nac uoY“
.ecno ta lla yppah dna ylenol gnileef fo noitanibmoc a
.derevocsid tsuj ylbaborp dah eh gnos emos ot nehctik eht ni gninnips dna gnicnad
.elbitapmoc %001 eb syawla ot gniog t’nera ew
seye ym revoc ot
sdneirf ruo rof ylralimis sdnuos ruo tes eW
,uoy tuoba yrrow I ,yppah t’nera uoy nehw esuaceb
t’nevah I ekil ton s’tI
”.yako gnileef ton er’uoy nehw llet yllausu nac I tub ,gnikniht er’uoy tahw wonk ot dneterp t’nac I
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.efil taerg a saw sihT
.os od ot hguone gnuoy llits saw I elihw daeha egrof ot gniyrt dna
trap tnatropmi na gnissim si eb ot derehtob yletulosba saw eh es-
”.em ot klat ot tsuj sgniht esoht od ot evah uoy ekil leef ot uoy tnaw t’nod I
?sevlesmeht revocsid ot elpoep era esle woH
.gnigassem saw ohw wenk htob ew os
”.sevlesruo ecnalab ot yaw a dnif si od ot deen ew tahW  .rehtie
”?won od ew od tahw ,oS“
,niaga htaerb a koot nailuJ ”,kniht I“
nehT“   ”.ecin yllaer neeb yllautca s’eH“
.aedi doog a saw ti thguoht htob
”?uoy t’nevah ,siht revo flesruoy gnirutrot neeb ev’uoy ,nuH“
”?era uoy tahw naht erom eb ot deen uoy taht syas ohW
,taht ekil gnihtemos gnicaf er’uoy fI“
”.ecaps uoy evig ot
,thgif a gnivah tuoba gniht doog eno ehT
truh…yam…yam tuoba klat ot tnaw I tahw…fi od I od…tahW“
.tuo dna ,nI  .htaerb peed a ekat ot uoy tnaw I ,trats uoy erofeB“
?ti htiw evil I dluoc ,llitS
– neppah ot gniog saw siht gnileef a dah I
”?hguone ton I ma yhw nehT“
dneirfyob ym dna
gnilims saw eh tub gniyrc neeb dah eH
.dennuts ylralucitrap gnikool dna pu gnittis
.thgir ton s’ti tub taht od uoy yhw wonk t’nod I
ni er’uoy esuaceb emit eht lla gnikrow morf derit erew uoy dna
”?em ot klat uoy t’ndluow yhW
.mih ot ti dednah
.shtnom wef tsal eht ysub os neeb evah eW
esuaceb ti tuoba ytliug tlef I dna ,suoires si sihT
ekil I ,haey…em roF
.moor gnivil eht ni ,won gnicap saw I
.dessik ew sa em revo gnimool ydob sih
,ylmlac dias nailuJ ”,nuH“
.t’ndluohs uoy nehw stnemeergasid ro sthgif evah ew nehw emalb eht lla
?gnorw s’tahw ,nuH“
.os ylthgir dna ,sevitarran reeuq ni ,desserts netfo si noitatnemirepxe fo ecnatropmi ehT
?mih ta yrgna steg dna aidem laicos sih sklats ohw revol xe yzarc eht emoceb I dluoW
d’uoy taht em htiw pu def os teg tsuj d’uoy
.em ffo gnippird saw sserts dna yteixna hcum oS
”,ezigolopa ot evah t’nod uoY“
dluoc eH  .em morf yawa toof a saw eH
,em fo tnorf ni etalp a tup eh sa reduol tuo dellac nailuJ ”?stopS“
ym detcepser eh
.gnol siht rof no og ti tel evah ton dluow yletulosba dna
,god.ecioveht ta
”.gnihtyna rof emalb ot erew uoy taht thguoht reven I  .em ot ton ,erew reven uoY
.delworg nailuJ ”!oliM“   ”—em
”.lanoitar yrev gnileef m’I kniht t’nod I dna
.era uoy nehw uoy htiw tneitap erom eb nac I
.hcum os dias taht yrrow fo esnes a gniyevnoc ecaf sih
.klat em gnittel llitS  .yltneg deddon nailuJ
.em ffo thgiew taht fo emos gnikat saw nailuJ tub ,gnihtyreve redluohs ton ot ,flesym emalb ton ot drah saw tI
.yrrow dna tnetni htiw em no desucof seye sih
stessa eht no gnikrow hsinif ot .M.A eht otni llew gnikrow saw I dna
retrams hcum taht tsuj yllausu saw eh hguoht yllaeR
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
em tih spukaerb
,elihwa rof dekrow ti
.em rof retteb hcum os xes edam tI  .devol osla
dneirfyob ym dna
tel taht loots retnuoc rab eht no nwod tas dna delims I    ”!era ew ereh
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb
.xelA morf saw tI
”.etib I nehw ti ekil uoY“
.gnihtyna od uoy ekam t’nac I“
yaw ehT  .duol eht gnirahS
,tsuD ot emoC seires eht fo srohtua oc era ohw
”?gniod uoy era tahW“
.moor eht ni esle enoyna naht
.pu ti gninepo tuoba deklat ew nosaer eht t’nera uoy dna ylgu t’nera uoY
ym…em neht dna enohp sih ta gnirats saw nailuJ
.rekihhctih flowerew
gnihtaerb ym tub %001 t’nsaw I
.seye s’nailuJ ees dluoc I os
.tuo kaorc ot deganam I ”,ysub neeB“
,tsael ta ,ton m’I taht uoy nwohs reve I evaH
,eenk ym no dnah sih tup
ot evah I dna ,sgnileef ruoy dna uoy tcepser ot evah I
”.enola ti ssecorp ot gniyrt saw I“
”.reveN .nuh ,taht rof uoy demalb reven I tuB
.deddon nailuJ hcihw ot ,deticer I
,kcab ym otno em dehsup eh kaeuqs a htiW   .lasuora dna
”?ew t’nera ,lufsseccus ytterp er’eW“
detnaw I  .ysub oot rO
.em rof dehsinif nailuJ
,uoy ot riaf ton s’taht tub ,tnaw I revenehw xes evah ot modeerf eht gnivah
.efil tcefrep tsomla nA
,xelA morf ti gnitteg neeb d’I esuaceb elihwa ni ti dah t’nevah eW
eh sa desolc htuom sih tpek eH
,regnuoy saw I nehW
”?retteb elttil a gnileeF“
.lufwa si ot esolc os m’I enoemos gnisol dna dlrow eht ni gnileef tsrow eht si ehcatraeH
”—tsuj I ,enif m’I“   ”.oliM
.ecaf denrecnoc dna seye mraw esoht ,srae lufituaeb ,dednuor sih dna ecaf emosdnah sih ta gnikool
?mih oT ?em ot neppah dluow tahW
”—I esimorp I yako m’I“   ”—ev’uoy ekil kool uoY  ?yako uoY“
.stnemom eseht dah I nehw
.saw ti skrahs elttil ni derevoc srexob eht htiw no oS
”.ti dessim I yrros
,deirrow os neeb dah I
.htaed ot mih evol llits dluow I doog siht kool t’ndid eh fi nevE
.deriuqni ylsuoituac nailuJ
.senomroh sih yb ylno dednammoc saw eh fi sa
uoy gnikcatta m’I kniht ot uoy tnaw t’nod I os ,nem rehto htiw tpels
.gnirewsna erofeb sthguoht sih delipmoc
dna od ot detnaw ew tahw no desucof os emaceb htob eW
.oud cimanyd siht ni fehc eht eb d’uoy desseug evah dluow reven I“
”?wonk uoy ,yb pils tsuj sgniht gnittel erew ew taht eb ot detnaw ew ohw
”.etib t’now I esimorp I ,erom em ot klaT“
?sevil ruo niur ti dluoW
,sruoh elpuoc a rof rehto hcae was ylno ew nehw syad erew erehT
a…detnaw I esuaceb tsuj dah ew gnihtyreve gniodnu ksir I dluoC
.xes pu-ekam eht saw
.kcatta yteixna na fo egrev eht no tlef I sa rehtegot meht gnignirw
m’I…hcum os gnitruh er’uoY  !uoy ta kooL
,uoy tsurt I ,em tsurt uoY
.eciuj egnaro fo ssalg a flesym teg ot tnew dna keehc sih dessik I
.pu dnah a tup I tub kaeps ot tuoba saw eH
dna nepo si nailuJ htiw pihsnoitaler siH
.srevoc eht rednu worrub ot yrt em edam dna ecaf ym no nwod demaeb nus eht
,sih fo srae dednuor ylbaroda esoht ni sdop rae sih dna stnap amajap emos gniraew ,nailuJ ees ot nehctik eht otni tuo deklaw I
,erom ecno sdnah ym ta nwod dekool I dna dekcarc eciov yM
eslup ym dna dewols dah
,dah tsuj ew eno eht sa livic sa eno neve
.won thgir deen uoy tahw
”.uoy htiw sgniht esoht gniod ssim I
.mih gnitruh yletinifed saw I woN   ”.nuh
I emit yreve hguorht ees dluoc eh wohemos dna detarelot reven nailuJ gnihtemos saw tI
.taht od ot hcum oot ecaps lanosrep dna htlaeh latnem
.T.O hcum os gniod ton m”I erus ekam nac I..nac I“
,yako eb ot gniog syawla er’eW“
.lla ti fo tcepsa lauxes eht redisnoc neve t’ndid I tub dekan yltsom saw eH
.nehctik eht morf ffo og enot railimaf eht draeh I nehw dnopser ot tuoba saw I
”.em ot gniyl er’uoy woN“
taht fo emos ffo tel ot ,detsurt htob ew ohw ,elpoep dnif dluoc ew tub srevol gnieb
”?maet a sa ti hguorht krow ll’ew dna em ot klat t’nac uoy taht uoy nwohs reve I evah nehW
gnihtemos ni gnikcal si ,taerg gnileef elihw ,efil sih taht ytilaer eht htiw detnorfnoc saw oliM
,srehto ro flesruoy truh dluoc taht gnihtemos od ot gniog ton er’uoy tsurt
.taefed fo yalpsid citamard tahwemos a ni meht gnippord dna pu sredluohs sih gniggurhs
.derit erew uoy thguoht I esuaceb enola uoy tfel ev’I  .rehtona eno
.deffuh nailuJ ”,oliM“
erehw loohcs hgih ni neeb dah spihsnoitaler esoht ,sediseB
.ni gnidloh saw I sbos eht kcab dloh ot deirt I sa drawrof gninael
.evots eht no gniog sgge dna nocab dah eh was I
”,lliw uoy wonk I“  ”!lliw I“
”.won thgir deen ew tahw ton s’tI
?em evael dna pu tsuj dluow eh erehw denigami I dah soiranecs ynam woH
”,snoitautis eseht tnorfnoc t’nod I fi nur gnol eht ni erom flesym truh ll’I tahT“
.em erofeb ekawa saw nailuJ ,lausu sA  2 fo 2 traP
.siht ekil stnemom dah ew nehw
.smsagro eh retfa peelsa sllaf eh ,sulP
.deneppah gnihtemos
em dlot dah tsipareht ym tahw derebmemer I
,erom klat ot deen tsuj eW“
”.era uoy kniht uoy fi neve ,melborp a t’nera uoY
.gnikcarc morf eciov ym peek ot gniyrt elihw wollaws a htiw
”?yllanif deb fo tuo uoy tog nocaB“
.llew ti ekat dluow I taht ylevitinifed yas t’ndluoc I
,noitatnemirepxe retfa
,yppah t’nerew uoy wenk I tuB“
,dlrow eht mih evig ot detnaw I
.eciov sih ot enot nrolrof a htiw deerga eh ”,thgir er’uoY“
.dnah ym rof tuo dehcaer dna denworf nailuJ
,emit emas eht ta tub ,ylbirroh nailuJ gnitruh pu dne dluoc I trams t’nsaw I fi wonk I
?dellifluf dna devol leef em ekam t’nod uoy syas ohW“
evol htiw llews em edam em dnuora gnipparw nam siht fo noitasnes elohw eht—
larips evitagen eht morf pu thguorb neeb gnivah
.gnol siht detsal dah spihsnoitaler suoiverp ym fo enon tub ,drah
”.taht ekil elam diputs a m’I  .on yas ot gniog ton m’I dna su fo owt eht fo reinroh eht m’I
”…uoy dnuora dlrow eht no sucoF“
.dluoc eh tseb sa rehtegot seceip eht gnittup saw god reywal tnaillirb
ton si tnemirepxe siht taht gninimreted
,pu tas dna deddon I ”,yakO…O“
”.uoy rof toN  .eromyna ton s’ti llet nac I…tub
,onnuI…detaudarg ew retfa tuB“
reerac a ,seussi lacidem dna sllib
”…tsuj s’ti…tsuj s’tI“
.smlap ym ni ecaf ym gnitser dna kcab dnah ym gnillup
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.redluohs ym no dnah sih tup dna dnuora deklaw eH  .pu eno edam
.nam detnelat ,emosdnah ,lufituaeb a era uoy ,oliM“
”?pu dekrow lla uoy edam siht sah mih tuoba tahw
.nocab llems osla dluoc I
.flesruoy gnimalb yb sgniht yfitsuj ot gniyrt potS  .ti potS“
.syad esoht ot kcab thguoht eh sa edis eht ot daeh sih detlit dna taes eht no detfihs nailuJ   ”?yllacisyhp
gnitcaer mih derutcip I dah syaw ynam woH  ?dam teg rO
.daeh ym deddon dna delffins I
,ni neeb dah I lootsrab eht otni kcab thgir laerehte eht hguorht llef I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.ssensuoires fo enot a no koot eciov s’nailuJ
”.nuf evah dna tuo
”.sruoh rof ti tuoba deklat eW
.noitsuahxe htiw miws daeh ym gnileef dna gnilffins ,daeh ym deddon I
uoy…tuoba deklat ew os dna
.dekooc eh sa nailuJ ta dna nehctik eht otni kool em
mih emaceb dlrow ym dna rehtegot dekcol selzzum ruO
,seye ym denepo I nehW
.sdnah ym dleh dna dehgis eh
,deppots eh em was eh nehW
”.oot ,em htiw tsenoh
.dnuora deklaw dna deffuh nailuJ ,su neewteb afos eht tup I nehW
yawa dnah a dellup dna desolc seye ym dehcnelc I
ksir I dluoC  ?erom tib
”.uoy ot pu nepo enoemos ekam t’nac uoY“
.deddon nailuJ   .dereffo I ”,krow ta
.klat ot woh wenk eh woh fo esuaceb etabed a niw syawla dluoc eh taht dekoj netfo eW  .delims nailuJ
.dedda ylkciuq I ”,eil a s’tahT“
”?rovaf a ksa I naC“
.pih eht ta denioj syawla erew yllacisab ew ,egelloc ni dna regnuoy erew ew nehw taht wonk I“
,esirprus ni dias oliM
tsuj m’I  .em evol t’ndid uoy fi flesruoy gnitruh dna gniyrc neeb evah t’ndluow uoY“
.detartsurf gnileef saw I tub ,mih ta reven dna mih ta toN
,emit tsaL  .fleseno rof
,setsat ruo ralimis woh ,era ew tcefrep woh rettam on tuB
.ffulf tsehc sih otni t’nsaw ti ekops I nehw os elzzum ym denrut I
?semitemos tuo em ekat uoy naC“   ”.syawlA“
.animats ruoy flaH“   ”!?tahW“
,nac I sa yllanoitar sa sgniht eseht hcaorppa ot deen I taht dias osla ehS“
.xes rof erom uoy ot emoc osla ot deen I“
.gninrom eht rof tnemtrapa eht dnuora raew ot srexob esool emos dnuof dna tesolc ym ot tnew I ,detelpmoc ksat gniyonna taht htiW
”?oliM“  —I ma yhW  ?tsrow eht gnimussa
ekil seussi laer evah t’ndid I dna
.em ta thgir drawrof denarc dna dekrep deniamer ,enim ot ralimisnu ton ,srae dednuor siH
”evoL fo esaC tuhS dna nepO“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT      .I
deracs saw I  .efil ruO
.seye ym depiw dna deksa I  ”?I t’nerA“
.em llet tsuj ,xes evah ot tnaw uoy fI“
.yadrutaS yzal a ekil tlef yadot tub ,sfeirb ym ni dnuora gnilworp dnim t’ndid I
dna emit gnol a rof ti tuoba deklat eW“
”?dab leef uoy nehw uoy ot netsil ot gnilliw
dna ecno ta lla rehtegot kcab deppans sthguoht yzarc yM
.detartsurf erom dna erom werg eh sa remrif gninrut eciov sih ,dias eh ”!oliM“
?xelA htiw od ot gnihtemos sah sihT“
kniht uoy dluow yhw…tahW“
?oot gniyrc eh saW  .eciov gnikcarc a htiw nageb nailuJ ”,kniht I“
.seye eht ni em dekool eh ,esuap trohs a retfA
”?tcilfnoc gnidiova tuoba uoy llet tsipareht ruoy did tahW
.srehto rof krow lliw
”?hguone t’nera uoy syas ohW“
nem erom htiw peels uoy—
I taht htiw tpels yllaer reve d’I nosrep tsrif eht ,yllaer ,erew uoY
.deffuh eh dna knip fo edahs a denrut srae s’nailuJ
.ypmurg em edam ti dna…doom eht ni t’nerew uoy dna gnihtemos ro emiT hcnurC
.gnihtemos reggirt uoy erofeb taht pots s’tel oS  .kniht I
”?esrow sgniht ekam rO  ?uoy
depmuj ew…kniht I“
”.detavitom doof ton fi gnihton m’I“
tuo sdub eht fo eno dellup dna ,delims
.su niur d’I deifirret saw I“
,em dedlocs ekaf eh ”,dab si hcihW“
,elttil a pu lruc dna
?uoy htiw enod eb d’I
.esle gnihtemos fo esuaceb erudne t’ndluohs yresim yM
deretnec flesym tpek I  .deppord dah
.uoy evol I yhw s’ti dna ,traeh gib a hcus evah uoy ,oliM“
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.daeherof ym dessik dna delims nailuJ
.od ot tahw erus t’nsaw I taht dnim ym ni delarips snoitseuq ynam oS
.deb ni uoy gnivah ssim I tub
ro…skcarc eht hguorht pils sgniht tel ot gnilliw erew ew taht hcum oS
.reggirt doog a saw taht ezilaer dna esuap em edam nailuJ  .ti pots ot dah I dna revo gnikat saw larips evitagen a ;thgir saw eH   ”.gnihtemos
.su rof ti dne dluow noitasrevnoc siht taht gnol os rof
.ereh t’nsaw eh fi ekil eb dluow efil tahw tuoba gnikniht tpek I
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots
taht s’ti…taht s’ti…xelA etah I taht ton s’tI“
dna em ot txen tis ot devom nailuJ ”,tiaw ,nuH“
,nwod tas dna denaorg I
?ti htrow flesym gnitruh saw
.esolc em gniward ,smra sih htob
.egassem txet euqinu a fo dnuos gnilknit ehT
.yawyna deddon nailuJ tub lacirotehr yltsom saw tI
,gnilarips er’uoY  …tuo dna…nI
.desucof syats eh erus gnikam ton m’I fi hctiws a gniworht ekil s’tI
retteb a saw I fI“
,ylfeirb nwod dekool dna denworf god detniap ehT
.ylpeed sevol eh nam eht fo
.tsehc sih morf pu ecaf ym gnitfil ton ,deddon dna koohs I
”!?taht od I dluow yhW“
.pihsnoinapmoc dna ssenippah rof ecifircas ot gnilliw neeb dah eh
rep suolaej t’nsaw eh elihw
.taorht ym ni wol delworg I ”,nailuJ“
ew…thgir er’uoY“   .emag ym rof
.yppah htob erew ew os ecnalab a tuo erugif ot dedeen eW
,gnithgif t’nerew eW“
saw eH  .t’ndid eh tub detnaw eh fi em hcuot
.uoy rof tsuj pu ti nepo t’ndid I dna ,haeY“   ”.maets
,llew sa tcennoc ton…wonk uoy