”.lraH ,yaD s’enitnelaV yppaH“
.’niog teg retteb eW .nom’c woN
uoy…uoy taht dootsrednu eh ,hu eH
.ecnatculer tuohtiw yllaicepse ,flow eht htiw eerga ot dah I ,yltnecer emit tsrif eht roF
,yllacinorI	   .nepo eht ni decneirepxe reven d’ew snoitome dna tsul fo dleifelttab a emaceb pihsdneirf ruo
”.gniht ruoy tog uoy…uoy tub
,edisni gnipeerc thgilnoom elap yb otni enohs seye thgirb-ecno sih rednu sgab yvaeh eht gnieeS
.neht etarepsed erom demees dial gnitteg fo tcepsorp eht nehw ,sneet-dim ruo ni deneppah su rof emit tsrif
,traH ydrA yb uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb
”.dednim-nepo s’yelraH ,haeY“
.doog nwo sih rof suoituac oot saw nhoJ
.gnir tnemegagne sih rO
,erom od…dluoc eW
.ssik gnitrap eht ni detcartsid neeb ton I dah
.gnihtolc tuohtiw llits
.noitcere etaidemmi na em gnivig rof tnelat a dah raob eht ro
eno siht piks esaelp
I	  ”!doG hO…ti s’taht
,wonk’y…ot thguo eW“
.thgin taht mih no emit ym dedib
.yelraH ot og ot emit saw tI
,elbanigami sehctap derediorbme dna snip yhcrana hsirag tsom eht dna sekips latem htiw tekcaj mined a dna sgnaf sih erew noissessop dezirp tsom s’noil niatnuom ehT
,derepsihw dna spil ym dekcep flow eht ,mih ot kcab gniddoN
.tekcaj eht rof lufknaht em edam
,rood eht hguorht tsrub ylneddus ydobemos esac ni ssik etanoissap ,kciuq a neeb d’tI
”,wobniaR dlO eht ekiL“  ”?wobniaR dlO eht ekiL
.emit tsrif s’nhoJ dna em ot derapmoc ton tub
.rehto eht ta stuohs truh dna sraet lufniap eht dehs ydaerla d’eW
.regnol hcum ,hcuM
,pit sih dehcuot eson dloc ym nehw repmihw flow eht gniraeh nopu delkcuhc dna ksum sih delahni I sA
,knalc duol a htiw rood dekcolnu ylpmis tsuj eh ,rehtaR
.gniddon morf flesym pleh t’ndluoc I ”…haeY“
.kcen ym fo kcab eht otni flesti gniyrub tuons sih
,hatU fo lla ni sedihwaR eht fo rebmem tuo ylno eht eb ot dah yelraH ,wenk I sa raf sA
,ksam s’retsej a ekil elzzum sih no dehcte elims das eht
,ylisaenu ekops eH
.daor eht nwod deps ew dna ,dnatskcik eht yawa detoob eh sa efil ot devver yelraH s’yelraH
,tekcaj sih no dehctap lluks enivob a fo ogol yreif taht ees ot elbakatsimnu t’nsaw ti ,em sdrawot denrut kcab sih htiW
,esolc em degguh eH
.ilaC ni elbaliava wef a etiuq s’ereht tuo snruT
.’pihsdneirf‘ ruo fo tnetxe lluf eht nwonk yeht dah
,shcamots ruo detaoc muc toh fo stej gnitrups retfa ssem ykcits a ni rehtegot yal ew ,retal sdnoceS
.hcamots ym dnuora smra sih gnileef em ot del ylneddus taht gnitfihs yb dewollof
.12 mooR morf gnimoc naom duol a ot noitnetta elttil diap sa llew sa
,slewot letsap s’moor eht fo eno htiw ruf ym ffo deird I
.em tsniaga dekcor eh emit emas eht keehc ssa thgir sih deldnof I
,tecuaf eht htaenrednu enola setunim net doog a tneps I ecnis
?reh noitnem ot ediced ylneddus I did kcuf eht yhW
,desuap eH ”…era owt uoy dnA“
.roolf ecnad a tog yltnerappa s’eno siht tub“
.redluohs muelortep eht ssorca sracs deyalpsid ylduorp tekcaj sih ylno
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
,sicoV sumoD yb
,dekaeuqs sserttam
.sreksihw ym delkcit elahxe peed siH
,ssik gnol rehtona otni su gnirb ot tsehc gniknits ,ytaews sih pu delwarc I emit eht yB
.taorht ym pu delbbub naom A
,tniop egatnav sti morf su ta gnirrats llits ,tas ti erehT
.eciohc sih edam d’eH
.eromyna ton ,t’ndluoc eH
.sedart lla fo flow a ,traH ydrA yb
.owt dnuor a od su tel neve ebyam
ro myg rehtie ni rehto eht fo secnalg kciuq gnirutpac yltnelis
,noitaroda elbidua ni mrof elam ym ta gnilevram ,ydob yrruf-ssel ym tsniaga flesmih gnidnirG   .dnekeew a tahw
,yliratnemom dekrep srae sih fo enO
.enim detcelfer sgnaf sih ni gninihs ssendas ehT
,skcos rof evas ,sehtolc ruo lla dehs ew emit eht yB
.ecalp s’rehto eht ta revo gnipeels tneps emit suoucipsnocni na gnirud
,erahs d’ew tnemtrapa ynit a ni levon ralucatceps taht hsinif dluoc eH
.regnol yats ot em lepmoc dluow hcihw ,seye sih ni kool deniap eht ees d’I ,esiwrehtO
,tsirw ym otni etarbiv selkcuhc sih gnileef ,hcamots s’dneirfyob ym dnuora ylthgit dezeeuqs I sa dna
,sruf rehto eht tcaf ehT
.ti tuoba deklat ydaerla su fo owt ehT
,yawa dellup eh nehw em ot elims das eht denruter neht
.dnik nwo ruo htiw yppah dna eerf eb
.nwonknu eht otni ffo derats ew
”?emit tsrif ruo rebmemeR“
.kwahom dliw a eb ot desu taht rufdaeh tpmeknu ,ednolb ytrid yb ffo deppot lluks kciht sih
,stekcajthgiarts ni stnerap sih tup ev’dluow ymodos dettimmoc ew syaw suoirav ehT
.wobniaR dlO eht ,hA
ehT	  ***  ”.oot uoY .varT ,oot
uoY‘ ,etouq I dna ,dias eH-eH“
.xob noisivelet eht morf gnimoc cisum eht evoba esir skaeuqs ’sserttam eht edam ylraen thgiew denibmoc ruO
.rebmemer ot thgin doog gnikcuf a reh gnivig dna roolf dnoces eht no pu smoor eht fo eno otni ereht pu—
.yldnof derumrum I
.sksut sih dniheb tperc nirg a ,noitcerid ym ot gninruT   ”!yelraH ,yeH“
.trihs pu-denottub sih htaenrednu rehtruf gnillevart swap ym ot em del yllautneve dna rrup gnideen a otni deohce tI
,eno em evag ylniatrec ehS
,wobniaR dlO eht ot kcab liat nrut ot thguos em fo trap delevirhs A
.hgis tnatiseh a delahxe I
,ksa ot dennalp eh fi sa
.niaga specib dna tsehc sih ta levram dluoc I os ffo ti deleep yllautneve ew ,sregnif ydaetsnu htiw nottub hcae gninetsafnU
.sthgil samtsirhC ecalp-fo-tuo eht
.stnemevom gnitsurht
.weiv otni emac srab fo wor niatrec a dna
si yrots s'yadot dna
.yraw tpek setimodos rehto eht neve hcum woh dewohs
.tuognah a etiuq s’ti ,mih dlot sah ssob s’yelraH tahw morf dna
.selcatnet ekil dehsarht sliat ruO
,varT“ .eerf tonk sih deldnof I emit emas eht rufdaeh ym hguorht sregnif sih gninnur ,stnap etarepsed neewteb derepmihw eH ”…varT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.sih ni smra ym gnidloh
.ydob ym ot resolc smra ym guh em edam taht
,levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna
.sthgiltops rolocinhcet ni klawedis yci eht dehcnerd sthgil noen riehT
,eulb eht fo tuo tnemecnuonna tnemegagne eht erofeb ,siht enod d’ew semit suoiverp ehT
,enim ot esolc desserp ,did llits yehT
.nesohc d’eh efil eht htiw noitiurf ot emoc dluow levon naciremA taerg txen eht rof saedi sih detbuod I
,mih kcuf annaw
.elims a gnimrof morf flesym pots t’ndluoc I ,hgis peed a pu gniviG
.noitatuper a dah ytiC sdaorssorC ni 9 letoM ehT   sicoV simoD yb
,deprihc eH ”.uoy rof dooG“
.esuoh eht ta nwo sih no gnieb ot mih detsurtne stnerap s’nhoJ nehw ytisrevinu erofeb htnom tsal eht neeb d’ti
.nihc ym nwod dna pu sessik deliart nhoJ
?huh ,rab yag A“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoT
.erahs ot regae naht erom neeb dah yelraH hcihw fo emos
”.yawyna ecivres tsafkaerb yttihs tog s’96 letoM ehT“
”.edud ,ti ekil d’uoy kniht I…d’uoY
,kcab dna lleh ot deniats steehsdeb eht gnitteg rof ezigolopa ylteiuq did I ,eno roF
.moor letom eht otni em gnitivni ylteiuq erofeb don suoetruoc a em evag neht
H“   .did esle gnihtemos ,rehtar rO
uoY“	 	  ”.yaD s’enitnelaV yppaH .nhoJ ,eyb-doog…“
.swoble ym gnigguh ot em del gurhs A
,smoor eht fo eno morf gnipacse deew fo llems gnicitne eht derongi I
;em evig ot dennalp d’eh tneserp eht detacsifnoc stnerap sih(
.ebab ,oot uoY“ ,delkcuhc eH
,eerf yaw sti debborht kcoc ehT
,renroc eht dnuora deraeppasid yllanif 9 letoM eht litnu
dellup I ,nruter etsahc on fo tniop eht ot ylesolc gnirepat ,egde lauxes eht ot hguone esolc nhoJ dehsup I ecnO	   .did ew dna
,tnatsni taht ni eugnot ym tuo tuc ot detnaw em fo traP
.spil ym pu tperc elims a nehw saw tahT
.hguoht gnikniht lufhsiw neeb d’tahT
.tekcaj ym barg ot kooh eht ot tnew dna pu kcab flesym desserd I ,drow a tuohtiW
,hO“	  .devol reve I nam tsrif eht morf cisum ekil deticile snaom fo surohc gnol a yb dewollof
?em ekil ytiC sdaorssorC evael ot hguone evarb leef eh t’ndid yhW
.dnatsthgin eht morf em ta derats tI
)thguoht dnoces a tuohtiw egabrag eht otni ti dessot yeht ,yldaS
.prat denethgit fo reyal a rednu dekcap sgniht ruo lla dah ekib s’yelraH ot dehctal reliart ograc dniheb-llup ehT
.nikserof eht otni eugnot ym deppils I
,esacriats nedoow eht pu ecap ym gninekciuq dna stsif otni swap ym gnihcnelC
)tcirtsid loohcs ssa-roop eht
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
enitnelaV tsaL ruO
.delims yltfos dna taorht sih deraelc eH
,hguoht ti tsniaga dediced eH
.xes eht retfa hcum sa klat t’ndid eW
dooG“	   .eldnah rood eht denrut I taht yawa dellup nhoJ nehw ylno saw tI
,reilrae derahs d’ew noitale emas eht ot kcab em thguorb tI
”.gnizeerf ’nikcuf m’I
.82 mooR no yal noitnetta ym ,oN
,gnihcleuqs ,gninaom
?tsrif ruo fo em dnimer mih htiw ssik hcae did yhW
,esion dnuorgkcab sa level etairporppa na ot pu emulov eht gninut ,lennahc VTM eht ot no noisivelet eht gninrut retfA
,reyalp drocer s’dad sih no ot netsil ot smubla ralupop ni gnikaens dna
.em pota mih dellup dna ,wam sih otni kcab eugnot ym demmaj I ,eil taht hsinif ot ecnahc a mih gnivig tuohtiW  ”—evol I…I“
flesym ekil enilef knup a—
”.lla dna gniddew eht rof deticxE
,kcen gnitaews sih otni naom I ”!hA !hA“
enitnelaV tsaL ruO saw sihT
.traeh ym ekorb ti
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,degnahc ylno ton gniddeb eht dnif ot tuo deklaw neht
.dnekeew eritne na rof su ot esuoh eht gnivael
,gniht taht no yrotsih eb erehT
.flesym tub ydobon ot derettum I
yadhtrib htneetneves ym rof tfig esirprus a sa em dessik eH
”.tsrif ti did I os
.anuas dehsinruf a neeb evah llew sa thgim moor letom ygnid eht ,wolgretfa ruo ni gnitnap dna toh os neeb d’eW
.detaluclac neeb dah
,eromyna stneduts egelloc niatrecnu ro sneet gnilbmuf t’nerew eW
.nevaeH gniretne erofeb lleH ni efil sih fo tser eht dneps ot detnaw dna su revo ytilibats nesohc d’eH
.tsap ym fo espmilg erom eno hctac ot daeh ym deleviws I
:saw dnim ym no thguoht tsrif eht ,yltcerroc em devres yromem fI
.efil ym fo trap tnatropmi na erew
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.evol ni nellaf d’yeht dezilaer htob yeht…yad eno nehT
,niard eht otni yawa hsaw ot demees erofeb morf thgiew ehT
dna( secnatsmucric ot eud sdneirf emaceb yehT
,anozirA ni gniddew ’sdneirf a ot tnew yehT
.reverof gnuoy eb ot gniog t’nsaw thgin ehT
.niaga dlrow elttil nwo ruo ekil tlef ti nehw
,evael ot gnitruh no tpek ti erom eht ,ereht deyats ew regnol eht ekil tleF .did ti ,haeY“
.lana derreferp reven
,etatS hatU ot tnew flow rebmit eht ,enil eht nwod sraey wef A
.evom tsrif eht edam eh
”?rehtegot yppah yllautca ,ekil…“
,hcaeb a gnola klaw
.gniliar ynoclab eht tsniaga gard a gnikoms strohs thgit ni nexiv gnidoorb ,teiuq eht derongi I
.ainrofilaC enola tel
,ylsuolucitem dennalp erew rehtegot sthgin ehT
”?gniod enirehtaK s’woH…woH“
”…sivarT ,yaD s’enitnelaV yppaH-
.flow eht ot kcab nrut ot ton derad I tub ,tuo dewolf yllarutan sdrow
.yelraH saw yelraH ,niaga nehT
,hguoht thgin tahT
,sdaorssorC ot yaw cinecs sti gnikam nees eb ydaerla dluoc gnirpS
.ti raen pets ot detpmetta esuol hsigguht ro eiknuj on ,erew srab yag eht erehw sa hcus doohrobhgien a ni sdaorssorC ekil ytic a nI
.mih gnigduJ .su gnigduj
.derewsna I ”.era eW .haeY“
,ksa ot em rof hguone detapissid taorht ym fo kcab eht ni pmul ehT
.liat ym fo hsiws a htiw delggig I ”.ereh emaS“
.nevaeH otni gnitteg dna ytilibats rof modeerf ecifircas ot dennalp nhoJ ,elihwnaeM
,esle erehwemos og ot hatU depacse ev’dluoc eW
,ti revo dehcnuh nhoJ tub
.ssa s’reltsuh a rof gniyap tneps retteb eb dluow yenom eht fo tsom nehw yllaicepse ,retrauq dna lekcin hcae htrow spukooh ticilli fo ksir eht edam thgin elgnis a rof ecirp eht ,dnoceS
.ecarg devas nhoJ tub
”.rab yag a si me‘ fo enO
”…rekcuf uoy ,pirg a teG“
.sserttam eht fo egde eht revo mednat ni dehsiws sliat ruO
.ksum enilef dna eninac kciht ni su fo owt eht gnihsaw dna ,ruf eht gniniats ,hcamots ym tsniaga dekael kcoc tcere s’nhoJ
.ecneirepxe fo sraey hguone htiw seidob s’rehto eht gnirolpxe ydaerla erew ew
,’96 letoM‘ eht ti gnillac dekil sbrubus ybraen eht ni gnivil sknup erutammi erom eht fo emos ,eno roF
.oot teews laer s’eH“
dna hsuls ydnas yb decalper yllaudarg erew wons fo selip lufitiP .ytic dira eht
.niaga ecno ria rof detrap eW
.kooh ybraen eht no tekcaj mined ym decalp yldrawkwa I sa su dniheb rood eht desolc nhoJ
.oot ti deredisnoc t’ndah eh fi sa dewaffug nhoJ ”?yllaeR“
,wobniaR dlO eht fo tuo dna ni gnidaeh serovinrac eht yllaicepse
,gnirumrum ,slwoj sih dekcil nhoJ
.elttil a egde no em tup did ecnatsid eht ni neris ecilop a gniraeh tub tol eht ni dekrap srac wef dah 9 letoM ehT
,gnizilaer tuohtiw sdaol gnikael osla saw I demees tI
”?truh drawretfa gniyats diD“ ,denoitnem eH
.8102 ni ,yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT
,noziroh eht revo deraeppasid ydaerla eniltuo s’tI
.edisni dnuof eb ot seiromem doog ,dliw fo ytnelP
,nisnocsiW fo sretniw citcra eht gnivarb ton s'eh nehw noitcifnaf dab gnidaer emit sih sdneps ohw
.noisufnoc ni daeh sih gnitlit mih ot del elggig deredliweb A
.nevaeH fo noisrev ’stniaS yaD-rettaL eht ,rehtar rO
,deb letom a ni tuo ekam tub gnihton enod d’ew emit suoiverp eht kniht I
,em rof gnitiaw tsuj mih morf raf dereets
.elbuort otni gnitteg dna sdworc gnorw eht htiw syad sih gnidneps
.elzzum ym retne ot noissimrep rof gniksa eugnot teews sih
.noertaP no seirots sih fo erom dnif osla nac uoY
.kcap eht morf hserf etteragic a otni sffuh tnecer fo detsat htaerb siH
.taorht gnilbmert ym fo kcab eht depacse hgual a dna ffocs A
enitnelaV tsaL ruO  yojne esaelP
.ezag s’flow rebmit eht thguac esle ydobemos tub
.deb desusid eht gnicaf renroc eht ni riahc a no dedracsid yal siH
.smra sih otni gnitlem
,dloc eht morf su tcetorp ot hguone did taht tekcaj rehtael a erow raob egral eht ,em ekiL
,rehtegoT .redluohs sih no nihc ym detser I
”!oot eM…oot eM !hfM“  ”—
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,tesnus eht otni ffo elcycrotom sih edor eh sa smra ylrub s’yelraH ot kcab
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
nhoJ	    .sekorts citsaisuhtne dna seporg neewteb gnitnemirepxe
ehT	 	  .dnatsthgin eht no gnir sih tes nhoJ
.dnetrab dluoc I stnioj yna swonk ssob eht fi ees ot yrt annog s’eh dna ,keew txen mih erih ot regae s’taht pohs ekibrotom a s’erehT
etad morp roines ym gnikat derebmemer I
”?taht dias yllautca eH“
.em dna deb eht neewteb gnikcilf seye
,oramA naS ni revo gnitrats yelraH dna em fo thguoht ehT
.kcab gnilims ylluftsul ,nihc sih morf loord depiw eH
uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots sihT
.rewohs ot tnew I sa tesolc a morf steehs eraps eht tuo llup ot mih gnivael
,su fo owt eht neewteb raw dloc drawkwa na sa ffo detrats tI
,ytinrete na ekil tlef tneserp ym ot tsap ym morf klaw
,roolf ecnad lautca nA
.niaga snis sih fo enitsirp ruf dennat ym gnivael
elihw hgiht ym tsniaga flesmih gnibbur nageb nhoJ
,gninrom lit‘ em gnitcepxe eb t’now yhtaK .ti htiw no teg
.kcuf kciuq ro ,bojdnah ,bojwolb elpmis a naht erom od ot depoh I
”.gnihtyna gniod pu dne ew fi em tsniaga ti dloh t’now eh dias eH
.drawtsew tfel gnicaf lirtson yenob eht
.ylikeehc deddon I
”…efil elbaresim ruoy fo tser eht rof ti terger ll’uoY“ .t’ndid I tub
.ecnartne gnitivni eht morf teef ytnewt doog a edir dekrap sih tsniaga yllausac gninael mih dnuof I sa
.surohc tsrif eht gniyalp nageb dnab kcor evitanretla nA
ehT	   .gnilffins ,dias eH ”.varT ,eyb-
ot…ot tuoba m’I ,nhoJ-
”.dooG“  ”?uoy era woH…woH“
.rewsna eht wenk I
.emirg dna sletsap thgirb ni denrettap niatruc rewohs paehc eht ta gniralg
”.thginot ro gninrom rehtie yb evael ot ydaer s’eh em dlot yelraH“
,ni flesmih etivni ot flow gib eht detcepxe tsomla d’I
.ekam ot ton esnes hcum oot edam ekoj eht ,eno roF
tahW“	   .dael ekil tlef ylneddus erow I stoob ehT
.thgis fo tuo serised lanrac ruo gnisaeler tneps ew emit eht detcirtser sdneirflrig )sih( dna yteicoS
,metsys retsof eht ni pu werg noil niatnuom knup ehT
.detpecca yldetnetnoc tey yltnatculer I guh a otni em llup ot desu eh eno emas ehT
,gninaorg ruo morf su tcartsid t’ndid ti teY
.rehto eht revo tca xes eno no desucof ew tniop eht ot
.stsirw ym gnisserac ylevissessop
.erusaem lauqe ni ssik eht denruter I ,esac eht revetahW
,hguoht nwod peeD
.su revo dessap ecnelis drawkwa ,yvaeh A
J“ .epan sih otni gnilzzun dna gnippal
.spil eht no mih kcep ot drawrof deppets I ,gnihguaL
,redluohs ym otni delffins nhoJ
.enif gniod s’ehS“
.htmraw ciglatson ni decalretni sregnif ruO
.rehtegot sessalc emas eht ni eb ot meht gnicrof
.loohcs hgih ni flow rebmit a tem eh ,nehT
.stnemhsilbatse ehcin neewteb gnidnetrab gnivil a edam noil niatnuom knup eht elihw tuo gnah llits dluoc yeht gninaem
.regnif sih no sih fo gnir taht ta dekool eh yaw eht deciton d’I ezilaer neve t’ndid ylbaborp eH
.seitnewt ylrae rieht ni htob ,flow rebmit nomroM a dna noil niatnuom knup a :siht erutciP
.dniw fo lwoh a revo pu ekops I ”.yelraH“
wobniaR dlO eht ot yaw ym no dehs I sraet ehT
.emoh kcab derednaw stseug rehto eht dna deb ot tnew ydaerla ylimaf egral ym nehw ,ytrap yadhtrib ym fo flah rettal eht gnirud
,sniev ym otni gnipmup detrats ydaerla tips sih hguorht gnisruoc enitocin eht rehtiE
,gurhs llams a htiw demrifnoc I
,emit lanif eno sevlesruo yojne ot gniog yllautca erew ew fI
llihcdniw gnineve na yb rof pu edam saw llafwons yraurbeF hcum fo kcal ehT
.ainrofilaC ni rehtegot efil a gnikam dna ,ytic dira eht dniheb gnivael
.kcab rewol sih nwod dna pu swap ym dekorts I
,retaeht eivom eht ni kcilf tsetal eht ees ot thgin a no secnawolla ruo gnidneps ,sessalc gnippiks/gnidnetta tneps syad eht neewteB
”’.em yb enif s’taht
.nevaeH ekil etsat spil s’nhoJ
.>i/i< fo esaeler lyniv a
.ytinrete suoirolg a ekil tlef ssik eht tub
,flow eht htiw evol ni llef knup ehT
.sdaorssorC morf ssim ylraed d’I secalp ylno eht fo enO
”…regnol elttil a tuo eb ot uoy ’nitcepxe saw I“
.citnarf erom werg gnittorf hsirevef ruo emit eht yb thgindim ot resolc dekcit setunim ehT
.sedart lla fo flow a
.sedarap eht fo eno dnetta
,haey…dnekeew a tahW
.gniddeb eht otni knus dah taews hcum woh dezilaer ew dna
ehT	   .eb ot ti detnaw d’I naht yrotasucca erom dednuos enot yM ”?nhoJ ,ti si
.pu kcab dekrep ylthgils srae s’nhoJ
.eman ym dias eh nehw bonk eht ta desuap I	  ”?sivarT“
.hguoht t’ndid eH 	 ”?os kniht uoY“
.erehwesle derevocsid eb ot seno rehto eht tsgnoma ezilairomem ot depoh I seiromem fo dnik eht erew yehT
.ssik elyts-nretseW a em reffo enola tel ,smra dinac gnorts sih otni em llup ot nepo rood eht knay t’ndid eH
.yug taerg a s’eH“
”.yug gib ,yaD s’enitnelaV yppaH“
.mih dniheb thgir nwod tas I dna ,elcycrotom sih no nwod tas raob eht ,taeb elgnis a tuohtiW
.sgniht ynam fo tnuocca no
.regnol gnitiaw ni tniop yna t’nsaw ereht
.enim tsniaga kcoc dna eugnot thguof eh erom eht kcab sih gnola ruf esned eht otni gud swalc tnulB
,gnol yelraH rof hcraes ot evah t’ndid I ,ylikcuL
.sgel sih neewteb gnignah htaehs demoorg-llew ,kciht taht fo tuo rebmem sih esaet ot eugnot enilef ym desu I nehw gnillirht erom ti dnuof eh tub ,yaw rehtie og dluoc I
,ssecca mih detnarg yldalg I
.erac ot noinu s’rehto hcae ni tsol oot erew eW
.dnah tfel sih no detnilg gnir tnemegagne nA
.mih ta pu elims ot yawa spil ym
,su neewteb egdirb ot erp fo dnarts llams a gnisuac
.noisseccus ni semit eerht dekconk I retfa rood eht rewsna t’ndid eH
.deb eht no nwod tas I dna ,taorht ym deraelc I
.ssik lufgninaem ,lausnes erom a yb dewolloF