.resolc gnimoc sevooh nevolc fo dnuos eht draeh dah eh ecno llaw dekcirb-enots eht tsniaga flesmih desserp xof ehT
rebmahcdeb eht ot ecnartne eht morf daerps gur der ,gnol A
.liat xof fo hsalf a deyaws hcihw fo meh eht htaeneb
noitalocihcam eerht htiw denil saw ecnartne eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
etarc a no delttes ezag sih ,aera egarots eht tuoba gnikooL
ti dehsats dna tsehc laer eht nekat ev’I
.enola mih evael ot mees t’ndluoc ohw sneh eht htiw gnitrilf ysub saw gnik eht neve ,yawa ekorb yllanif eh nehW
.nihc ot wap tup hguoG   !nmaD
.teuqnab s’thgin eht rof gnivirra ylregae tbuod on
.meht sdrawot detlob eh
,dlohserht eht ssorca ylthgil gnidaert ;evom sih edam hguoG nehw tnemom siht ta saw ti dna
W“   .enipluv rehto eht no pirg sih gninesool yllaudarg reraew eht
s’hguoG   ”.mirgesI dneirf dlo ym neve ,swollag eht ta daed em detnaw tsaeb yreve ,gniht txeN
.decitonnu yletelpmoc enog ton dah eh ,xof gnuoy eht ot tsnwonkebnU
”.rewot nretsew eht edisni morf emac ti ekil sdnuoS“
.tsop rieht gnidnats snoillats owt eht morf ecnalg a neve tuohtiw llah taerg eht hguorht pils ot elba
,nepo dehcni rood eht setunim nihtiW
.ezis sih flah tuoba
was eH .peek eht fo srood eht ot denruter seye s’enipluv eht
.ereht ylraen ,won emoC
,enorht sih nopu tas naws dlo tnecifingam a ,egats eht fo tfel
dluow I ,nwo ym enutrof s’htenmaL edam I fi tlef I esoppus I
,seenk sih ot knus xof gnuoy ehT
.deppans kcip tsrif eht sa neve
.enipluv wollef sih fo ffo seye sih ekat ecno ton did eh ,feiler ni gnihgiS .don saw
tnew ecnartne s’hguoG ecniS
.ylgnignol edis ’sonkyK ta deleenk sneh owt
,debrab fo tip yhtgnel a saw sdeer sti htaeneb
thguac kcip eht tog tub ,srelbmut dnoces dna tsrif eht dnuof ylkciuq eH
”?elbareferp eb traeh eht ot resolc peek nac uoy taht gnihtemos t’ndluoW
dna wodniw s’rewot eht ot etarc eht dehsup ylluferac xof ehT  .tcefreP
ylpeed deffins rehcra ehT
esicrexe tpmorP yadsruhT eht ni tnapicitrap lanoisacco
.tuo aera eht epocs ot gninruter erofeb hsiruolf a htiw kcab dellac hguoG ”.ma’am
.yal tsehc a erehw deb dezis-gnik lufitnuob
snetram enip detacixotni fo puorg llams a rof evas
tohs sih koot xof eht
,raf os yrotciv elttil eno .…lleW
t’ndid I  .rehtegot sdnuorg eht fo sedis owt eht degdirb hcihw
?llew sa deppart yboob saw tsehc eht fi tahW
,naretev a fo kool denedrah eht dah serutaef sih ,ees dluoc xof eht tahw morF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
– lerekcoc a dna lwo na – sdraug eht fo smrof detaticapacni owt ehT
”?esidarap fo klim eht knird dna
.tneconni tsomla raeppa mih gnikam
.laeuqs a tuo tel sdraug eht fo enO
.emirp sih tsap saw ,yb og ot gnihtyna erew ruf gniyerg sih fi ,ohw xof a gnilaever
.ylirgna hguoG deksa  ”!?uoy era ohw-
!rairf hsiloof a yb enodtuo eb ot ylno siht lla hguorht og
.htaeneb ebor nworb a gnilaever ,teef sih ta llaf ot brag layor eht wolla ot naht rehto
,rood eht ediseb dehsad hguoG ,tceffe ekat dluoc ytivarg erofeB
.tnereverri dna nezarb yllauqe llits tey ,tfos saw eciov siH
.xof gnuoy eht thguoht
reveohw ro tahw rof gnihcraes llits ,segdeh eht gnoma dehsad eH
.sraob erew hcihw fo tseraen eht dnuof ,pag eht hguorht gnireep nopu hcihw
.srelbmut eht rof dnuora gnileef ,kcol eht otni tsrif eht dils eh ,yletacileD
”.seitiliba ruoy esuba ot nigeb dna lufedirp emoceb lliw uoy ,saw I ekil tub ,eurt
.ssap ot emoc siht dluohs tuo mih llup ot emoc dluow enoyna detbuod eH
”!luficrem eb ,drol ym esaelP“
llaw s’yeliab eht gnola meht htiw devom eH
.eye s’der eht ot raet a dna ecaep fo esnes a thguorb hcihw fo sekil eht
.wollof ot hsiw ton yam uoy taht htap a nwod uoy ekat lliw tI
.stnavres layol tsom ruoy gnoma ma I !gnik dooG“  .waj
doow dehsilop saw ngised stI
.esion eht desuac taht saw ti
,naws emosdnah a gnitciped niatnuof detplucs yletarobale na saw meht raeN
.dnah ta ksat eht ot derapmoc yalp s’tik ekil demees ti tey
taocrus etihw dna eulb a erow raob ehT
.flesmih dedleihs xof ehT
.deniamer llits xof debor eht tsel
,ecnatsid eht ni tnurg feirb a saw erehT
,esolc pu ,tnemom siht ta saw tI
,dih egdeh eht tahw was won hguoG
.elbram gnirettahs fo hsarc gnittilpsrae eht yb dewollof ylkciuq
,nwod tperc dna dednecsa eh sa
.nwo sti no tfeh a etiuq dah hcihw
,meht draeh dah ydobon ,wohemoS
– sdraug eht trela ot ton luferac
.evolg a ekil dnah ’snaws eht gnittif tlih lufecarg sti
dna dlrow siht dnoyeb reh ekat yltneg dna reh fo edisni teg
”?erusaert s’gnik a htiw ffo ekam ot sa dlob os eb ot flesruoy sa hcus tik rebmil ,evitpecrep a hcus sgnirb tahW
,rewot eht fo roolf driht eht gniraeN
,htaerb a htiw dna seye s’hguoG thguac egats nedoow eht ot pu gnidael sriats ehT  …ysae oot hcuM
,toof fo teelf peek ot erus saw eH
.sdrow s’htuoy eht decal ytniatrecnU
;gnideecorp morf der eht derreted yran ti tub ,ssenkrad etelpmoc ni deduorhs saw roiretni sti
,em erofeb ti ot teg nac uoy fI
,eltsac eht otni dna
.oga gnol erew semit esoht hguoht ,ma I tahT“
.tsethgils eht ni laer t’nerew yeht gnizilaer
,os tsuj egde eht ot ti desiar eh sa tnurg a ecnelis ot tseb sih deirt
,ekops taht raob regnuoy eht saw tI   ”.ere‘
.esruc a dna gnisselb a htob si ,eno gnuoy ,tahT“
.noihsaf drazahpah a ni
;ylfeirb senots sih gnihctulc wap a htiw
pu flesmih dellup hguoG ,htaerb a gnikaT
,rewot nretsae-htron eht
.segap yrruFoS dna
epac ruf a ni flow yerg a fo ecneserp eht
yaw a hcus ni devrac enam sih dna etanro erom raf saw nworc siH
detoof-thgil eb ot tseb sih did eH
,raef htiw ediw seye ,kcab deppets hguoG
.yb og ot gnihtyna erew
.feiht eht tsniaga liat yhsub sih dehsurb dna delims dranyeR
,tpek ylsuolucitem saw roiretni ehT
,tcapmi ,reduol ,rehtona yb
.peek eht fo noitcerid eht morf emac hcihw
.elkcuhc tfos a tuo tel dranyeR
,htrim fo lluf dna thgil saw eciov siH
,tfos saw eciov siH
”!suoutpmetnoc os gnihtemos od reven dluow I
dewollof saw ecnabrutsid llams sihT
rethgual desuma ,delffum fo dnuos ehT
.decudorp yllanigiro saw krow siht hcihw rof
erofeb repmihw lufraef ,tfos a tuo tel eh dna ti fo thgis eht ta gnitaeb deppots ylraen traeh s’hguoG ,raeb nworb a fo ssenekil eht dleh
na si eH ,6102 fo eve eht ecnis ytinummoc orhtna eht rof gnitirw ylraluger neeb sah ohw
,R‘   …dengis saw eton eht ,mottob eht tA
.elbitsiserri saw thguoht yrev ehT
,yldipar tperc xof ehT
.tuhs rood eht dellup eh dna
,daeh sih denroda nworc A
eht otni telbog ssarb a desiar eH
.edistuo sraob eht fo eno dias
.smra sih otni kcab gip eht dellup
.gnimehcs ydaerla dnim sih ,doots dna tsehc eht fo dil eht tuhs hguoG
tub…eno gnuoy ,yrt
”?hguone neeb evah muludnep eht t’ndluow…ssendooG“
.peelsa tsaf nellaf dah
,gnitpmet a fo toof eht ta saw sihT
reivaeh erew yehT .sksam elbram eht hguorht gniggid nageb erugif eht ,ylteiuQ .dega
:dias ecno ,reywaS ,rotnem sih gnihtemos derebmemer xof ehT
.mih evoba wodniw eht fo dloh thguac eh sa gnitnurg
.ytilanosrep laivoj a deyarteb seye s’raob eht tey
ot sknaht ,rehtie ksam a tuohtiw saw ohw eno ylno eht t’nsaw enipluv eht ,ylikcuL
!ecalp ni llits si kcol eht dna
lergnom a suoicilam woH“
.elbram morf detfarc
.stnalp eht fo sehcnarb rewol eht gnikram
eht dessapyb eh sa tsuj kcol eht no mrif deniamer sucof siH
peehs ,sesroh ,sgod ;woleb gnikool
htap eht gninil sehcrot eht fo wolg tfos eht ees llits dluoc eh ,nwod kool ot gniraD
eh…enola ton m’I ekil skooL
dnuos eht yb dewollof
.dneirf dlo na ot
.wob a enipluv wollef sih gnivig ,pac sih devomer xof dlo eht ,ylsseldrow dna ylfeirB
,enap eht revo llef etarc eht ,retal tnemom a toN .thgil spets sih
pu til seye s’hguoG .resiw eht enon
,nepo rood nori ybraen eht desae xof eht
ytiniffAruF sih no
!oN   ?flesmih sonkyK gniK gnilaever ,nepo gnuws ylneddus srood eht fi tahW
;ti denrae ylurt t’ndah eH .nihtiw erusaert eht ro tsehc eht rof derac regnol on hguoG
.ydaerla saw eh naht erom dnah s’etaf tpmet eh tsel
,deksa hguoG ”,uoy t’nera ,dranyeR er’uoY“
, ainaH yb ”dexoftuO“
.wob sih ot dehcton ydaerla saw worra na dna
”.enotsmirb dna erif was uoy fi sa dekool uoy ,yhW .eno gnuoy ,flesruoy nees evah dluohs uoY“
.yaw hcihw yreve gnitrad ezag sih
,detresed ylegral sdnuorg eltsac eht fo tser eht gnivael
”?ris ,ta gnitteg uoy era tahW“
!meht ot tseraen hsub eht ni tnemevom
,htenmaL eltsaC fo sllaw kcirb eht dednecsa eh sa decar traeh s’hguoG   ainaH yb ”dexoftuO“   yojne esaelP
wedyenoh no enid llahs ew erehw sutrapelaM ot kcab ,em htiw emoc ot ekil uoy dluoW“   .seye eht ni enipluv rehto eht dekool dranyeR  .nageb elanif dnarg s’wohs eht sa gnimmurd fo dnuos eht saw ereht ,edistuO
,daeh sih gnikahS
ssensuovren ni spahrep
,serutaef s’hguoG gnoma elims tfos a deticile spil s’lesaew dlo eht gnissap sdrow esoht fo thguoht ehT ”.kcab
.tsal eht eb ot ton ti wolla kcul yam
.thguac saw eh fi skcots eht ni mih dnal dluow siht gnitpmettA
,ainaH yb ”dexoftuO“ saw sihT      .’on‘ yas ot
”.tset eht ot uoy tup ll’I kniht I“
,emosraef a saw eno sihT .naws eht
.ecnahc rehtona evresed uoy spahrep ,raf siht ti edam uoy ,llitS
sllaw nedal-
fo sllaw eht otni yaw sih edam eh sa serutaef sih derucsbo ti taht hguone ,ebor sih fo dooh eht desiar erugif eht ,siht htiW
a ni gnitapicitrap
.mih nees d’eh erofeb raf mih dellems dah hguoG .edisni deppets
”!gnidnatsrednusim a lla si siht-T !elboN gniK-K“
.detcartsid eb t’ntsum uoY !hguoG sucoF !oN
.daeh sih nopu pac derehtaef a gnicalp erofeb kcen sih tuoba kaolc neerg a denetsaf tsuj dah
,sksam detniap citsilaer ylgnikirts fo lluf saw tI
hguoG rof noitatpmet on saw erehT
.stiolpxe sih ni hsiloof yrev tlef ylneddus dna
.thgieh redluohs yletamixorppa egdeh a yb detarapes erew peek eht ot gnidael sdnuorg ehT
.srehto esuac thgim I mrah tahw gniredisnoc reven ,elbillug eht dna tneconni eht no skcirt dellup dna ,detaretluda ,elots I“
dna deraor gnik ehT
”.dniw eht tub saw draeh ew tahw kniht ey sselnU
,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
,ytpme saw tsehc ehT !?sevig tahW
.nwod ksam eht tes eh sa repmis a tuo tel xof gniga ehT
.niatnuof eht ta detciped saw taht drows yrev eht spahrep
,ksam eht htaeneb morf deohce
.dehcuotnu deniamer llits hcihw tsehc eht ot denoitom eH
,enivar evissam a gnikoolrevo
,sdraug eht brutsid ton tsum uoy ,hguoht luferaC
eciN‘   .ti dedlofnu eh sa elzzum s’hguoG morf kcuns lworg wol A
hguorht ,strapmar eht ssorca yaw ym ekam nac I fI
.xof gnuoy eht nopu nwad yllanif ot gnidnatsrednu rof ,seye esnetni ,derehtaew esoht otni ecnalg a koot ylno tI
.decneirepxeni dna
”.sevlow yb neve detseb eb ot elbanu ;stac dna sraeb fo retskcirT“
traeh s’xof eht edam egats eht fo kcab eht ta eil tahW
.egats eht pota nups gnieb elat eht fo ewa ni llits ylekil
– ydal a dluow uoy sa kcol eht taert tsum uoy
ralimis yrev dekool ,xof redlo eht fo seye eht ni ,dna tcatni llits saw ksam sihT .pu ti gnillup
.dnuos fo esnes neek s’hguoG rof ton fi decitonnu enog evah dluow ti
.lrans tnenamrep a ni dekcol wam sih dna seye gniknilbnu ,sselefil sih
.dleh gnieb era seitivitsef editnustihW eht erehw egats eht dniheb
.gnikat eht rof sruoy s’ti neht
,elzzum sih ot wap a dleh erugif ehT  .nihtiw
,ebor nworb dedooh a erow erugif ehT
,depmuls saw ydob sih ,dnoces eht naht redlo eb ot demees eno sihT
,dil eht ni deddebme saw erihppas a ,gninil dlog dna
.kcar eht ot tnes eb dluow eh ,citsidas ylralucitrap tlef gniK eht fI
.mih nopu nwod erob tac eht sa flesmih gnittew ylraen
.repsihw dehsuh a sa tuo emac sdrow ehT
,ylitsah pu enod demees ti tub taocrus dna liamniahc emas eht erow eH
redluohs sih morf gnuh reviuq rehtael A .dexaler erom
s’tac taerg eht ni tnemevom fo kcal eht no pu kcip ot deifirret oot raf saw hguoG dna eciov gnimoob ,peed a ni delworg noil ehT ”!sruoy ton si tahw ekat ot eltsac ’sonkyK otni gnikaenS !era uoy
.siht rof wolla ot sisylarap decudni-rorret sti ni nrobbuts oot saw ydob sih tub nur ot detnaw eH
;racs ro esaerc fo tros yna dekcal elzzum siH
.kcilc a saw erehT
raob gnitot-dreblah a dna
yletelpmoc desucof eh sa
.obezag eht fo noitcerid eht ni dehsad dna
...dratsab suoreneg eht etiuQ
.woleb yeliab renni eht ni gniyalp slertsnim eht yb decnelis ylno saw hcihw
…dna relbmut driht
,siht deksa xof redle ehT
.tnemhcrap fo eceip elgnis a rof evas
.cinut sih morf skcip fo tes a gnillup ,tsehc eht fo tnorf ni nwod tlenk hguoG
.emoclewnu eb t’ndluow noititepmoc elttil a…rehto eht no tub
.ediw seye sih ,knurt eht denepo xof eht ,ylregaE
.trohs pu emac uoy smees ti
.em erofeb ereh neeb evah tsum
,hguoG gnuoy rof rovaedne gnignellahc a saw tI
.elddif a ekil mih deyalp dah dranyeR dlo retfa ton
”!wohs gnippirg ,yas I“  .yrc a tuo tel dna ria
dworc eht dna sremrofrep eht htob gnivael
.nepo srood eht dehsup
,strapmar eht gnola yaw sih edam eh sa nwod tperc dna denrut
,pu dil eht dehsup hguoG ,dluoc eh sa teiuq sA
.tnew seltsac sa raf sa thgis lausunu na ton saw htenmaL
’?senob eht llor ot eraD
,srewot owt eht gnitcennoc strapmar eht gnola doots sdraug eerhT
.enim fo oreh a emaceb uoy dna tik a saw I ecnis serutnevda ruoy fo seirots draeh ev’I .yllaer elat gnol a s’tI“
.dnoces eht neht ,yaw eht fo tuo
,regnuoy dekool eno sihT
.moor eht fo kcab yrev eht ta
.renroc etalosed eno ni yrehcuabed fo tib
.resolc emac noil ehT
.smret elbatirahc no ton saw
,revewoh resolc yna teg dluoc eh erofeB  .IIXCMM :slaremun namor eht htiw devargne saw hcihw
dna htaeneb nrow d’eh cinut der a fo rovaf ni ebor loow eht dedracsid xof rehto sihT
,yawa dekcab hguoG ,gnitnaP
?ot emac sdraug eht fi tahw ,yrruh ot dah eH
,are sti rof levram a saw elacs sti hguohT
.detcepxenu etiuq saw dleh ti tahW
.sesnes sih gnimlehwrevo won seitivitsef fo dnuos eht
,ecaf s’noil eht fo erutxet elbram eht deciton xof eht nehw
.renroc eht dnuora dereep ylluferac hguoG dna weiv otni emac peek s’htenmaL ,nooS
”!?taht saw sezalb ni tahW“
.enod saw thgin eht nehw tuo htob meht gniwehc sonkyK gniK gninigami ,yb deppils eh sa delkcuhc ylraen enipluv ehT
.swap ym ni eb llahs erusaert s’htenmaL dna elbuort elttil htiw peek eht otni teg nac I
.rehtie ecneserp detivninu na eciton ot yalp rieht ni devlovni oot yllarutan erew egats eht no srotca ehT
,llaw eht ni pag edam ylwen eht hguorht gnicnalG
eht oT   .gnos ni etul sih fo sgnirts eht gnikculp tpek ohw tac a dna
.drows dratsab a htiw demra noil ,ralucsum
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.elzzum sih gnipacse morf rethgual suovren eht peek der eht dluoc regnol oN .sekips nori
,teef sih otno kcab gnilbboH
eye sih hctac ot tsrif ehT
,drows nailitsaC a saw dnah thgir sih otni devrac dna
.lufituaeb erom dekool ti ylno ,peek eht ni eno eht ot ralimis yrev tsehc a saw tI .pots ylraen
,mih dleh taht noil a fo wap eht ti saw roN
,seye gniyrp fo ytirojam eht yb decitonnu ylevitaler
,deen ylbissop dluoc eh naht sgnillihs erom saw ti ebyaM
.tnemom a naht erom rof pu kool ot thguoht dah edareuqsam eht gnidnetta eno on ylikcul
.tsrif eht dewollof drows taerg a htiw demra ,raob dnoces ehT
;ytimynona fo esnes a deniater xof eht
,relevart wollef ruoy
?xof elttil ,yas uoy od tahW   .gnik eht ron
oot ti dna rettal eht neewteb
rewot nretsew eht ot ecnartne eht ta detsop sdraug eht ,edistuo ecnO
,erugif a emac ,deppart won erew sdraug eerht eht hcihw ni rewot eht woleB
.elzzum s’enipluv eht ssorca tperc elims A
ereh gnieb s’xof gnuoy eht dnatsrednu yletaidemmi ot demees ohw gnik A
”?ti nekat I dah tneconni eht ot mrah thguorb evah I dluoW“
.mih fo eciton ekat ot teuqnab eht htiw devlovni oot saw enoyrevE   .esiwhtgnel
yrev gnihtemos ot dehcatta niahc
od dluoc xof regnuoy eht llA
.sreknihc no trohs yldrah si gniK nawS eht ,ton ylekiL“
.thgis ni erehwon saw xof debor eht dna ffo raf t’nsaw egats ehT
dna ecnartne s’peek eht ot yaw sih no deunitnoc xof eht ,liat yhsub sih fo hsiws a htiW
.hcnys tcefrep raen ni srae sih dellif sllaf toof dna taebtraeH
,thgin eht fo krad eht ni nevE
.egrahc a htiw segnih sti ffo rood eht hsup ot detpmetta sraob owt rehto eht sa tsuj ti gnikcol
.derewol ezag sih dna gnidnatsrednu ni pu til seye s’dranyeR  ”.era uoy sa derebmemer eb
dna mih fo htdiw s’riah a nihtiw emoc muludnep eht tlef eh sa llor a otni llef hguoG ,tnatsni na nI   .yvaeh
.llaw eht hguorht dehsams
.pu mih pirt dnim sih tel ot droffa t’ndluoc eH
htap sih dekcolb eritta layor ni desserd noil emosraef a
.doof htiw dellif selbat eht sdrawot mih fo tnorf ni dworc eht dehsup xof gnuoy eht ,yltneG
,tsedom etiuq yltnerruc si tuptuo sih hguohtlA
ytiragluv fo tnuoma yhtlaeh a yb dewollof yletaidemmi saw hcihw ,sleeh revo daeh
,sniatruc nosmirc eht dniheb gnidils ylkciuq
.kcen sih ot wap a tup yletaidemmi eh sa taorht sih ni saw traeh s’xof eht ,teef sih no gnidnaL
.gurhs tub pleh t’ndluoc enipluv eht ;saw eh sa detalfed nevE
a – desaeler gnieb niahc a fo
.mals a htiw tuhs rood rewot eht dellup xof eht
,esnopser on evag xof rehto ehT
,nepo ediw rewot gnirobhgien eht ot srood nori eht dehsup hguoG ,strapmar eht no pu kcaB   .htenmaL
,yrlever ni trap nekat dah tsaeb yreve ylraen ,edareuqsam eht ot sknahT
deworran seye s’feiht eht ,kcol eht otni kcip driht eht gnidilS
dna pu relbmut tsrif eht dehsup eh ,ylluferaC .ksat sih no
;ton dah der gnuoy eht tahw no pu dekcip gnivah
.dloc xof eht deppots dna
stnavres diletsum emos yb derucsbo erew yeht erofeb tsuj eye s’xof eht thguac yletaidemmi
”.tik revelC“ .desiar worb a
.neeb eva‘ tsum erehT“
.s’recnad a delbmeser ydob esohw
htaerb a ni werd xof der eht
.yeliab retuo eht ot sriats eht dednecsed eh ,ylsuoituaC
.devres eh gnik yrev eht htiw deppart saw eh edisnI
.derebmemer eh naht retrohs tib a saw hcranom eht ;noitnem ot toN
.gninil dlog a htiw
.enap wodniw enots eht no ylsuolirep gnireteet etarc nedoow eht fo edis eno htiw
dniheb tsuj doots eutats rehtonA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,owt ro tseug a fo espmilg lanoisacco na dna
.ere‘ luos a ton s’erehT“   .noitapicitna ro
;ffo ti dehsup dna ksam noil eht ot swap htob koot eH
.reteews eht lla eb lliw htenmaL fo erusaert eht htiw ffo gnikam neht ;pu loof tnagorra siht wohs ot ecnahc a rovas dluow I woH
,edirp sih fo deppirts
,pu flesmih detsioh dna
.flow eht dna gnik naws eht ,dworc eht htiw laed ot evah dluow eh edistuO
.xof rehtona fo taht tub
,ecnartne eht ssorca rab ward nori eht dellup eh ,ylkciuQ
sksam derettahs eht dna etarc dehsurc eht evresbo ot deppots ohw
.seceip ni neve ,elbareferp neeb evah dluow naht
,delbmert swap s’raob ehT
,niatnuom ybraen a fo edis eht no tliub saw ehS
,thgirla etiuq s’tI“
ylevol sti ,sgnik eht yB
.thgin doog dna uoy knahT  .resiw eht enon
.spets evif yreve sgnitniap htiw denil erew sllaw enots eht
,llew sa enipluv
gnos eht otni detaroprocni ”swoem“ suoirav eht fi ,enilef a yb demrofrep eb ot demees taht edaneres a ylralucitraP
.hguorht ssap ot sesuohdraug eerht dna
,pu tes a eb lla dluoc siht ,wap eno nO
”!yrroS“   .ega sih etipsed
doolb deird eht deciton enipluv eht
.repolretni eht ta kool tneiciffus a teg hguoG did tnemom tsal eht ta ylnO
,yeliab renni eht fo llaw eht degguh enipluv ehT
.sriats eht pu dnuob eh sa erutcurts ynit eht fo llaw nedoow eht dehsurb wap siH
.serutaef ciots s’noil eht gnimarf dna nwod gniwollib fo noisserpmi eht evig ot
.NGISLLAC htiw
’sutrapelaM fo droL
,noitarbelec dna ecnad ni gnigagne erew seidal dna sdrol deksam rehto dna
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy
.edisni kcip dnoces sih dehsup eh sa kcilf dna hctiwt ot nageb liat deppit-etihw s’enipluv ehT
obezag worran a hguorht saw htap efas ylgnimees ylno ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,lavivrus rof yrassecen ssenitfarc eht gniretsam ot yaw eht no eb ll’uoY
.ecalp drah a dna kcor a neewteb saw eH
,sgnitniap gniyrrac fo ssecorp eht ni
,mottob yrev eht ta ksam a deppirg dna depsag erugif ehT
.tnorf eht no nwes siL eD ruelF a htiw
…ecitcarp ruoy rebmemer ,hguoG thgir…raeD   .deppans
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.egats eht nopu ecnamrofrep citamard a ni derutparne erew stsaeb deksam fo aes tnarbiv eht sa ytivitca htiw gniltsub saw yeliab renni ehT
.cinut sih fo kcen eht yb hguoG hctans ot tuo dehcaer
.thgis lanrutcon yb dediug
doow dehsilop eht htiw gnolA
.erom ecno sgniraeb sih derevocer eh sa stnap neewteb ni repsihw a saw eciov siH
esuohetag tseraen eht morf gnidael
,kcol a kcip uoy revenehW“
.mrof enipluv sih hguorht gnitoohs enilanerda eht fo ffo hgih
”!ytlayol ruoy tuoba tsenohsid er’uoY“
,raelc saw tsaoc eht erus ekam ot tnemom a gnikaT
,gats a ,rentrap reh erofeb enipluv eht otni deklaw ylraen ehs sa wos ylemoc a deirC
.degreme driht eht sa tsuj
,niaga nwod kool ton erad eH
.neht dekrep srae
,dloc hguoG deppots kcilc a litnu…doog os ,raf oS