.ekil uoy revewoh yssup ym daerps nac uoy ,yob gib ,kcoc ruoy htiw ecaf ot ecaf m'I ecnO“
.spih rellams ,nwo reh tsniaga mrif meht dleh eH
.sih tem eugnot reH .htuom tew
"!elohliat ym tsniaga gnippals era sllab esoht litnu pots erad uoy t'nod dna ,gniog peeK“
,yssup tew reh htiw pu enil pit sih fo htmraw eht tlef ehs hguohT
.htmraw htiw dellif traeh s'allaC
.tenalpruF yb 9 gnaF sa hcus seigolohtna ni dehsilbup neeb sah dna
.edisni mih tel ot elzzum reh denepo neht dna
.yldrawkwa dias eh ",yrroS .thgiR .hO“ ".sgge
.tnemssarrabme htiw won gninrub saw ecaf reH
.enohp reh ta kcab neht ,pu decnalg allaC
.niatrec ssel dna reteiuq ,deksa nam eht
,uoy taht dekcohs fo dnik llits yltsenoh m'I
,tsehc dna ecaf reh revo rettalps ot deunitnoc nemes fo sepor sA
.ylteiuq deksa ivA
,deksa ivA ,yltnatiseH
.elzzum reh dehcterts nirg yoc A ".em
,rettOtnacifingiS yb
?yllaer ehs dluoC
.noitatiseh rehtonA
hu I ?neht ,etag ruoy si sihT !thgilA“
,reh dessik eh nehw tsehc reh ni gnirettulf eerfrettub eht tuoba ,leef reh edam eh lufrednow woh tuoba
.reh ot klat ot detnaw llits eh taht
sreh otni dezag seye s'ivA
,ecaf reh revo lla gnilbbird diulf kciht eht gnikatsim yna eb t'ndluow ereht
,tcejbo ot detnaw eh fi sa htuom sih denepo ivA
.erofeb ot sbojwolb nevig d'ehs skcoc nomékop eht naht regral raf saw eH
"!em rof nepo ti daerpS
.kcen dna ecaf reh fo edis eht nwod dna keehc reh revo derettalps nemes tew toH
.ruf fo daetsni riah yriw ,niht htiw
.trapa deggut sdlof reh tlef s'allaC ,euc no fi sA
.enog saw erofeb thgin eht elbuort hcum os meht nevig dah ohw krej eht ,revewoH
tfahs dezis-revo taht fo spals gnihcleuqs eht draeh allaC
,ereht doots owt eht sa ecnelis drawkwa eht fo tnemom a retfa nehT
.sih tem ylgnivol seye reH
,rebmun sih reh dlot ivA
.egdelwonk taht htiw laed ot devresed yehT
.meht ni dnuora deppilf d'ehs emit tsrif eht tahwemos denesool dah yehT
.reh hguorht nar revihs a dna ,sliat reh delkcit eH
.edisni sregnif sih deppid dna yssup reh daerps eH
.naom a htiw dias ivA
,koob a gniveirter retfa taes eht evoba ti wots ot tnadnetta thgilf a morf pleh tog
.enips reh nwod nar revihs A
.sgel reh neewteb nwod rehtraf ti gnidiug
.skeehc reh ot pu dehsur htmraW
.lla retfa ,gnihtyreve fo noitartsurf eht rof pu ekam ot dekcuf d'ehs namuh a tsuj saw eH
.yaw sih no deunitnoc yllufesoprup neht dna ,worb a desiar
.ylleb mils reh revo nwod dezag ehS
.htab eugnot laiceps artxe na uoy evig ll'I dna taht od uoY
.dne eht otno ijome traeh a dedda ylsuovren ehs
.dnats thgin-eno elbisnetso siht htiw srebmun enohp gnippaws ,gnorw tlef tI
.dias ehs ",nur attog ev'I ,kcuF“ .tihS
.hceeps nomékop dna ruf reh dniheb nosrep eht nees dah ohw
.reh fo edisni kcoc sih dednuop ivA sa dehcra kcab reH
,ffins artxe na koot reh ot txen gnissap moodnuoh a sa deppiks traeh reH
.erac t'ndluow ehs ,dezilaer allaC ,did yeht fi tuB
.erusaelp htiw reh gnitloj dna ydob reh gnihcra
,wam llams reh ni kcoc egral-oot sih bob ot tseb reh did ehs elihw
,osrot dekan sih ta pu dezag ehS
,derevihs dna desnet eH
.thgin tsal ot pu neeb d'ehs tahw tuo elzzup thgim taht nomékop eninac on
,reh dnuora dezeeuqs mra siH .detrats ivA
.dehsulf skeehc reH
tuo gnurps sinep ytfeh A
.seivom eht lla ni ekil avilas fo liart a neeb evah dluohs ereht taht tlef allaC .ekorb ssik ehT
,keehc s'nam eht deppuc allaC
,tsyrt rieht tuoba tuo maercs ot detnaw ehS
iuB thgilF thginrevO“
.sezeeuqs eltneg htiw selcitset eht ta gniporg
.ivA ta kool ot denrut ehS
.egassap tew gnikaos reh otni gnitsurht
.emit on detsaw eH ".stit
.ot deirt ehs ,lleW
.allaC hguorht degrus cinaP .41 etag ni gnidraob won saw ailetsaC ot 4135 thgilf senilriA navonU taht tnemecnuonna rieht deralb srekaepsduol ehT .desimorp eh
.uoy rof toh nmad os m'I .ivA ,dab os ti tnaw I ?tnaw uoy tahw taht si ,ti rof geb ll'I“
.snottub sih gnihsup saw ehs wenk allaC
",taht ekil flesruoy tuoba klat t'noD“
,dias ehs ",yrrow t'nod
.depsag allaC "!eniF“ ".niaga
.lla ta tropria eht ni esle eno on erew ereht ekil delaeuqs allaC
.reh deretnec ohw youb a
.toh os er'uoY .allaC ,kcuF“
.sdnats thgin-eno od yllamron t'nod I
.rovalf eht derovas dna wam reh desolc ehs
.dekcap d'ehs stcudorp ruf citauqa eht htiw ruf reh denoitidnoc dna d'oopmahs ylsuolucitem allaC
,naom ot ylno ssik rieht ekorb eH
.fo erac nekat em tog ev'I“
",lliw I teb uoY .lliw I“ ".niaga
.tuo thgilf eht no arepo paos otnaK a gnihctaw kcuts tog I
,niaga steehs eht no kcab denael ehs ,nehT
.noitapicitna esnetni ni mriuqs ot tnaw reh edam tfihs thgils yrevE
tfahs sih dekorts wap reH
.noitcetorp evah t'nod ,hu I“
.keehc reh otno tfahs sih nwod delbbird taht muc fo segitsev tsal eht gniraems
.ecrof htiw ni kcab neht dnA
.taeh htiw denrub ecaf reH
taeh dna erusserp eht democlew allaC dna
.epacse tel ot dennalp allaC pord ylno eht saw tahT
.ydob reh otni peed dehsur htmraw
.tilc reh revo detfird sregnif sih sa esnetni werg erusaelp ehT
,seenk sih ot nwod srexob s'namuh eht dehsup neht dna
.esae htiw aibal dekaos reh trapa dehsup erusserp ehT
.yrtnuoc sdrawkcab eht ni moor letoh a koob ot
.reh fo tuo kcab werd kcoc s'ivA sa
pit kcoc sih litnu ylno emit siht ,niaga nwod spih sih dnuorg ivA
.niaga mih ees ot teg d'ehs ,reve fi ,nehw wonk t'ndid ehs dnA
.esnetni erom neve saw tsurht txen ehT
,niaga mih ees reve d'ehs fi
.yot a ekil em dnuop ot kcoc namuh eguh ruoy tnaw I
.ecaf reh fo tnorf ni kcoc gnibborht taht gnikorts ylgnihtoos
.enohp reh otni ti devas yletaidemmi allaC dna
"!thgilf efas a evaH
.ffo ekat ot tuobA
?eybdoog uoy ssik ot drawrof oot eb ti dluoW
wap s'allaC sa dnuora ediw sa hctap tew A
.hcum taht lla gniod t'nsaw gnitfihs s'ivA
.kcas ytfeh s'nam eht ot nwod derutnev wap rehto s'allaC .tfahs sih dnuora laeuqs a deticile taht
.peels ot ffo detfird d'yeht erofeb
,waj gnihca reh dehcterts taht bob luferac a retfa ,tuB
,ivA detxet ehs ,yawnur sti sdrawot tperc enalp eht sA
"?uoy t'nera ,niaga em htiw gnikcuf er'uoY“
.sthgilf dessim derdnuh a htrow saw
,liat eht morf pu enips reh fo htgnel eht decart ivA
!enif m'I“ ".ecaf a edam uoY“
,moor letoh eht ot gninruter nO
,levart fo yad tsal sih rof drac tibed etaroproc sih llifer t’ndid ynapmoc s’ivA .tropria otnaK eht ni moor letoh a gnikoob seitluciffid nwo rieht otni nar htob sa
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
psag a htiw dehcra kcab reh ,neht tuB
.niaga drawrof tsurht dna kcab werd ivA sa demriuqs ehS
.spil yssup reh delkcit riah llab yzzuf siH
”yaL-iuB thgilF thginrevO“
.sllab sih dedaenk dna
.em edisni kcoc ruoy evah ot gniggeb
senotrevo larolf eht htaenrednu nemes fo rodo ygnat ,yhtrae taht dellems ehs ,llits nevE
.spil sih no ssik feirb rehtona rof drawrof desserp ehS
.pu derehtal dna ecin si kcoc ruoy tub ,retal siht hsinif nac eW“
.nomékop a ekil detnap eh sa nepo gnuh htuom nwo siH
.mih gnidiug fi sa
,yteirporp rof t'nerew ti fI
moor ynit eht ,kcilc a htiW
.melborp rieht saw taht ,ivA ssik reh gnihctaw eldnah t'ndluoc yeht fI
?og ylbissop eh dluoc peed woh—
.dias ehs "!ivA ,gib nmad os er'uoY
spil reh ot gnulc mucerp ytlaS
.ydob reh otni repeed dednuop kcoc s'ivA sa
,rehtegot moor a dekoob yehT
.doog saw siht ,kcuF .snoitasnes eht fo ytisnetni eht htiw demlehwrevo
,ytisnetni gnizzub eht dniheb dna
"?lasuora tew gnippird ym
.niks eht tsniaga dehsurb hteet reh emit hcae decniw ehS
,regnif sih dnuora spih reh delggirw allaC
,ivA morf yawa dehsur leziub ehT
.noitommoc eht ni reh fo tuo deppils regnif sih sa derevihs leziub ehT .ylleb s'ivA otni gud redluohs reh sa
.niaga sdlof reh tsniaga desserp
.lla meht kcuF .meht kcuf tuB
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.esuap a saw erehT ".sruoy
.efil laer ni kcoc namuh a nees reven ev'I ,tihS
.htuom reh ni tif neve dluow daeh sih fo egdir kciht eht rehtehw denoitseuq ehs ,tnemom a roF
.elppin rehtona desaet ivA sa
,dialp nwod decaf allaC
.eunitnoc ot uoy tnaw I“
delknirw erom niks eht
.reh revo gnimool namuh dekan ,nael eht ta pu dezag allaC
.ivA ,kcoc ruoy kcus ot nomékop siht tnaw uoy hcum woh em llet uoY
.ylsuovren delkcuhc ivA ".efil
?etag emas eht eb dluow ti demussa ehs dah yhW
.steehs delpmur eht fo pot no reh ot txen despalloc eH
.lla ti htaenrednu ssenrettib fo tnih a htiw ,ygnat dna ytlas saw dees siH
ivA ecnahc on saw ereht dna ,reggib ynA
.gnisaet lautum sih ta nirg tub pleh t'ndluoc ehs ,deen gninrub reh etipseD
.thgir os saw tnemom taht ni gnihtyrevE
.no dehcterts ecneliS
.hgiht reh tsniaga deddorp kcoc dekaos-tips ,tcere siH
.dnuora uoy ees ll'I“
"!tnereffid gnihtemos od ot em deen uoy fi wonk em tel tsuJ
.ti dezeeuqs yltneg sregnif sa
.ti fo demahsa t'nsaw ehs dna
.htmraw htiw reh gnidoolf
.koohs ydob elohw reH
.dezzub enohp s'ivA .ti tnes ehS
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.sniol s'allaC ni gninrub ydaerla deen eht dekots
,ydob reh hguorht nar redduhs A
,hu I“ .'~iub ,leziub' ,lausnes hcae htiw gnilbmur eciov reh
.niaga em htiw gnikcuf tsuj er'uoy ro ,ti tnaw yllaer uoy fi llet t'nac I“
.rettOgninnuR@ ,rettiwt rieht no denoitnem ro moc.yrrufoS
.ylleb ot ylleb gniyal meht htiw hgih oot raf gniddorp saw ti ,revewoH
.rehtegot thgit sgel sih gnizeeuqs
?allaC ,kcoc ym tnaw uoY
rosnops s’allaC sa gnitca ivA
,mlap reh ni tif ot egral oot saw kcas ehT
,mih dekcuf ehs ,haeY
.depsag ehs ",ivA ,kcuF“
,pit sih revo thgir kcil eltneg a dereffo ehS
.traeh gnidnuop dna noitanimreted yleets a htiw seye s'ivA gniteem
.kcoc namuh kciht htiw deffuts
,drawrof delruc eugnot reH
.pots ot uoy llet ll'I ,hcum oot s'ti fI“ .denaorg ivA
.flesreh taht eveileb ot detnaw ehS
pil reh tib allaC
.sdlof reh revo detser sregnif sih ,yllaniF
,erusaelp gniyfirtcele eht hguorhT
.yawa rehtraf dna rehtraf gniworg ivA
,esnet saw ydob reh ni elcsum yrevE .denaorg ehS
ecrof ni kcab dehsur neht dna
,mih desaet ehs sa kcen sih fo koorc eht tsniaga pu delzzun allaC
.selohssa esoht kcuF
.tnemom a rof etihw was ehS
,dias eh neht dnA
.steehsdeb eht naht esrow detnet erew yehT .srexob denottub
htmraw sdrawot nwod devled sregnif siH
.htuom sih otni gninaom dna gnikahs ,msagro reh tuo edor ehs sa
.mih ta dekniw dna
.allaC ,dnammoc ym si hsiw ruoY“ ".ivA ,em kcuF“
gnikamevol fo stuob elpitlum rieht retfa deird dah taht muc htiw rehtegot kcuts saw muc namuh yksum ,hserf htiw kcils t'nsaw taht ruf s'allaC fo hcni yreve ,gninrom eht nI
.tnorf reh dnuora kcab mra eerf sih depparw namuh eht
,ivA ,ti ekat nac I“ "—
.elzzum rehtona gnissik morf ecneirepxe neila na
.03 etag saw thgilf rehto ehT
.teews dna dnik os saw eh …tuB
.doog ro lufniap leef ot desoppus saw ti rehtehw llet t'ndluoc ehs taht ecrof hcus htiw reh hguorht detarebrever noitasnes ehT
"?owt dnuor rof ydaeR“
?uoy t'nod ,oot yssup s'leziub a ees ot tnaw uoY“
dluow taht skcabemoc revelc hguorht gnitros ysub saw dnim reh ,ksed noitpecer eht ot kcab deklaw yeht sA
,daeh nwo reh revo nwod daeh sih detlit eH
,setag sdrawot esoprup ksirb htiw devom nomékop dna snamuH
.dne eht t'nsaw siht tahT
.ppa gnitxet reh otni
.hcum os taht dnim t'ndid ehs …esruoc fO
,kcoc sih no deraeps ,demriuqs ehS
tnemom a rof reh edisni ezorf regnif siH .denaom ivA
.stit reh fo epahs eht tuo gnileef
.ydob reh erolpxe ot nam eht etivni ot noisiced pans eht edam ehs
.namow ytterp dna trams a hcus er'uoY“
,mraw a ot sreh dnuora daerps yeht dna
.namuh eht dnuora ylthgit spih reh gnihcnelc
.deipucco em peek ot deen I lla tog ev'I
.hgual a htiw dezilaer allaC ",hO“
rennid tnasaelp a ot depacse neht dna
",avonU tisiv emoC“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
allaC revo dehsaw
.reh pots t'ndluow snamuh sdrawkcab rehto fo sgnileef eht dna ,pirt reh no ssenippah dewolla saw ehS
.aibal reh gnidaerps
.niks reh rednu nettog dah pirt elohw ehT .ot detnaw ehS
.wam reh no nirg gnitae-tihs eht ees ot elbanu namuh eht ,deksa allaC
a hcus er'uoY“ ".evas dooG
.sruoy fo laed taht no doog ekam ot uoy rof emiT“ .derrup ehs
.drawrof dehsup eH
.ydaets flesreh dloh ot kcoc s'nam eht fo esab eht gnippirg ,demriuqs ehS
.knups s'ivA ni dehcnerd dna ymils ruf reh htiw kcab nwolf evah d'ehs
.ydaerla tew os saw ehs ,kcuF
.sgge em gnivig ton er'uoy
.deb llams ,elgnis eht erahs ot ivA detivni ylitliug allaC
,taorht s'allaC ni kcuts pmul A
,mih ekil detsat ti
,leziub gnilevart yltnednepedni na ,allaC ,emit tsaL
"?hcum oot …taht saW“
.kaeuqs prahs a htiw sdrow reh dekcarc tsurht lufrewop A .kcab tohs allaC
.revihs sih tlef allaC .dias ivA ",hO“ ".em
traeh rehtona dedda neht dna
.htuom sih tsniaga elzzum reh sserp dluoc ehs os steehs eht morf pu yaw reh demriuqs ehS .deddon allaC
,erised htiw gninrub skeehC
.raf oot enog d'ehs taht yrrow dna
,mraw a otni dedaf erusaelp fo stlob gninthgil gnimlehwrevo eht sa nevE
.reh ta kcab thgir dennirg ivA
,laer llits saw eh taht flesreh dnimer ot dedeen ehs fi sa
sregnif sih sa depsag ehS
.sdlof reh neewteb ylisae dekcils kcoc siH
.doog nmad os tlef tI .mriuqs reh edam tilc reh revo noitom gniggard ehT
sa seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
.ti desolc ylesiw tub
tcepser htiw reh detaert eH
.reh edisni gnimmuc sinep namuh evissam eht fo borht dna hctiwt yreve no ,noitasnes taht no gnisucof ,deredduhs ehS
?ereht nwod ti rof leef doog a gnitteg er'uoY
.did eh dnA .saw eH
.noitpecer mraw a htiw tem erew yehT
dna rellams hcum os tsuj er'uoY
.rae sih ot eganam dluoc ehs tsesolc eht
.erised dna erusaelp htiw hsulf saw ydob reH .derevihs ehS
.retsam a tuohtiw dnuora gnirednaw tep a sa reh gnitaert snamuH
,reh woleb knirhs tropria eht gnihctaw
.niap eht tuoba erac t'ndid ehs tuB
.ni ti pils ot deganam ehs
.pit eht tsap deppans dnab eht sa
.teews ylthgils detsat tI
snoitasnes fo yrrulf eht ta depsag ehS
.denihw allaC ",ivA ,tihS“ ".uoy
.niaga gnitsujda seye reh ,deknilb allaC
.dias ehs ",toh si siht ,kcuF“
.niaga evom ot gnirebmemer erofeb
.sih ot ydob reh gnisserp ,denaorg allaC
tilc reh fo bur esnetni artxe na htiw rovaf eht denruter neht eH
,sgel sih neewteb tcere kcoc namuh kciht eht
,duol tuo dias allaC
,reniart ,esaelP ?reniart ym er'uoy dneterp ot em tnaw uoy oD
.ekil skool ti tahw enigami ot gniyrt er'uoy teb I
,kcoc gnibborht sih elzzun ot ni denael allaC ,nwod deid msagro s'ivA sA
,edisni kcapkcab reh detfeh ehS
.eugnot reh revo thgir dednal muc sih fo tej a os nepo elzzum reh dleh ehS
.naorg elbidua na deticile tahT
.lufrednow saw namuh sihT
.mraerof s'namuh eht dnuora degguh wap rehto reH
.deksa eh "?allaC ,yako gniod uoY“
,gnidnopser yltsenoh erofeb desuap allaC ".erofeb nomékop a htiw xes dah reven …ev'I“
.kcab detxet allaC
.skeehc sih til hsulf der teeb A
,ni devled regnif A .delbmert ehS
?kcoc sih tif ehs dluoc dlrow eht ni woh—
dluoc ehs sa rovalf sih fo hcum sa pu kcip ot nikserof sih dnuora gnilggirw eugnot
.srevoc eht htaenrednu morf decafrus daeh reh sa seye s'namuh eht gniteem ,dias allaC
,sdlof yffup ym ,niks sselruf ,knip ehT
,ereht osla saw ivA tuB
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sdap wap s'nomékop a ekilnu os
!allaC ,llew sa uoy—I“ ".dnuora
,mraw reh htiw pu flesmih enil ot gniyrt
.sdlof reh detrap sregnif siH
.derettulf traeh reH
.oot no sthgil eht nrut uoy …fI“
.pit kcoc desicmucricnu
,dnabtsiaw eht otni swap reh dekooh ylideerg allaC .tnet taht fo kaep eht dekaos
.gnidne euqserutcip a devresed ti dna
.seciuj reh htiw dekaos ,denetsilg kcoc siH
"?thgirla si siht erus uoy erA“
eunitnoc ot noitacidni na sa taht koot leziub ehT
nwo reh gniteem ton seye sih
.hctorc sih tsniaga sdrawkcab dnuorg spih s'leziub ehT .llew sa gnilkcuhc ,dias ivA ",kcid
.ezorf sregnif siH
nomékop elgnis a
.sdnoces wef rehtona rof rewsna t'ndid eh ,taht etipseD ".pots
,tnemom sseldrow ,drawkwa na retfA
,ni denael ,tlenk ivA
*** ".leziub dekaos-muc ,yxes a ot txen kcuts er'yeht nehw toN“
.ksed noitpecer eht sa raf sa morf reh no xes namuh fo keer eht llems d'yeht
.reh dethgiled hcihw
,ti fo emoc dluow tahw wonk t'ndid ehS
.devom ehs sa elzzum reh fo tuo deppils kcoc siH
.reh edisni delruc regnif sih sa rae reh otni dehtaerb ivA
.tnemeticxe ni gnidnuop traeh reh ,desuap allaC ".htab
.reh kootrevo evaw rehtona sa gniredduhs
,retteb gnikcuf uoY
,pots ot uoy detnaw I fI“
.ruf reh hguorht deggard tI
.ksed eht dennam eeyolpme tnereffid A
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.thgir sliated eht lla teg I erus ekam ot tsuj—struh reven wef artxe nA“
,hguorht gnirewop fo sdnoces wef a koot ylno tI
egassap thgit reh edisni ecaps fo retemitnec yreve ,lluf ylbissopmi saw ehS
,nehT .delbmert eH
.uoy htiw ecnahc siht evah ot ykcul os m'I
,naom esnetni na hguorht deganam dna
.reh dnuora elpoep eht ta dnuora decnalg ehS
.steehs eht tsniaga pu yldetaeper deppawht sliat reH
.htiw reh dehcnerd dah ivA muc eht ni gniksab
.noitcennoc elbidercni na edam osla d'ehs
.stpmetta lareves hguorht gnilbmarcs pu dedne ehs os ,noitom htooms a ni rednu pils tsuj ot ecaps elttil oot dah steehs dekcut ehT
.yhw erus t'nsaw ehs tub
eciov reh ecreip enihw a tel ot ton drah gniyrt ,pil reh tib ehS
.sdlof derruf ylthgil
erusaelp gnibmun ,gnilkcirp fo evaw gnizzub A
.niaga steehs eht hguorht pu yaw reh delggirw allaC
,gninetsilg eht morf llef mucerp fo pird A
nezitic ssalc-dnoces a sa detaert ylgnitairufni saw allaC elihw
.kcoc namuh kciht sih fo lluf os gnieb fo esnes elbidercni eht
",uoy rof tew gnikaos si yssup ym dnA
.dnuora sllab sih dellor dna
.niaga mih teem d'ehs tahT
.ecnarussaer tsuj ,eciov reh ni gnisaet on saw ereht ,emit sihT
",reniart ruoy eb ot dneterp ot gniog ton m'I“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.ydob reh hguorht taeb erusaelp gnihca llud A
kcen sih fo edis eht dnuora pu daeh reh delzzun ehS
.nikserof s'nam eht htaenrednu gnisaet
.yawa gnileef taht decrof ehs tuB
.erofeb ezis ruoy namow a htiw xes dah reve ev'I yas t'nac I
.uoy rof ydaer dna doog m'I os pu em rehtal dna tuo ti gid
.lward yksuh a otni deppord eciov reH
.namuh doog a er'uoy …tub
"!ni ti tup ,ivA ,suecrA teewS“
.hctiws thgil eht tuo thguos
",yrroS“ hsipeehs a derettum ehS
flesreh allaC dnA
.thgilf reh ot txen tis t'ndid nomékop eninac a sa gnol sA
,wodniw enalpria eht tuo dezag allaC
.teef reh revo meht gnivael
.denediw seye reH
.lasuora reh htiw denetsilg tfahs sih fo edisrednu ehT
nam eht thguac d'ehs draug-ffo woh ta edirp a neewteb thguac saw allaC
.ylpmoc ot kciuq saw ivA .dias ehs
",yob ,em edir dna em fo pot no teg nehT“ .delkcuhc allaC
.htgnel sih dekorts eh sa tuo dettej muC
".thgir etiuq t'nsi elgna ehT
.reh edisni delruc dna yssup reh otni desserp regnif dnoces A ".toh
,reh fo pot revo debmilc eH
,tnemom a detatiseh ehS
.yrrufoS no selaTiuB
.yhw wonk t'nod I
.yssup deffuts-llew reh morf nwod dna ,stit
?yug roop eht rof hsrah oot sdrow talf esoht ereW .detatiseh ehS
,hguoht ,lla fo tsoM
,yticorpicer ni yssup s'allaC revo delggirw sregnif siH .denaorg ivA
.eciwt dlot eb ot deen t'ndid allaC
.eraps ot emit
.enohp ym ffo gninruT
,sllab nomékop morf tnereffid os dekool tI
"!em ssik gnikcuf ,pu tuhs ot em tnaw uoy fI“
.tnorf reh nwod gnireep
,taet reh ta yltneg deggut yehT
.spil reh neewteb tuo dehcterts muc fo liart ykcits A
.eroc reh pu deohce
.yawllah letoh eht otni tuo dekaens ehs sa dednuop traeh reH
.niks mraw eht revo stigid reh gnilruc
borht elbarusaelp A
.desuap sregnif siH
.reh rof tcefrep kcoc namuh lufrednow taht fo tsurht elgnis yreve ekam ot denoitisop
.dias yllanif ivA erofeb etunim a flah rof rehtegot demriuqs dna delggirw yehT
.snamuh elohssa ynam os tem ev'I“
.raey rehtona rof secaf sselruf ,talf ruoy fo eno ees ot dah reven I gnihsiw lanimret eht hguorht gniklaw saw I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.pit sih morf mucerp fo daeb a pu dekcil ehS
,snamuh htiw noitartsurf reh etipseD
.kcoc namuh ym kcuS“
.ruf reh revo kaerts pit sih fo ssentew eht gnileef ,derevihs allaC
”yaL-iuB thgilF thginrevO“   yojne esaelP
.ecniw reh edih ot pil reh tib ehS
.eugnot reh htiw snalg sih degassam dna
.reh fo edistuo llits
htgnel kciht ehT
.mih fo tuo desaet ti selggirw dna sehctiwt eht rof dna—
yllacitcarp m'I won taht noisserpmi na hcus edam uoY
.htap nwo rieht delevart ylizal yeht sa tilc reh revo sregnif esoht lriws ot mih rof deen gnihcnelc-tug eht
.deppiks traeh reH .deksa allaC
.tfahs sih gnola dekorts wap reH
"?rethgit neve teg uoy did woh ,allaC“
,flesti moor eht rof diap ehs elihw
.yllufthgiled delgnit tI
"?rebmun ruoy s'tahW“
,detnurg ehs "!hcni gnikcuf yrevE“
.hguoht ,teews er'uoY
.selppin fo wor dnoces reh ta deppots yehT .ruf renniht dna
,rettOtnacifingiS yb
,sdrawnwod gnitlit
!seivom doog evah yeht epoH
.namuh siht dekcuf d'ehs wonk dluow ffats letoh eht taht thguoht eht revo ni tperc tnemssarrabme ,tnemom a roF
.mih no flesreh detsat ehS
,erusaelp reh htiw drah dezzub sliat reh ,teknalb revo delbuod eht rednU
,htooms dna tfos os saw tI
"?neht ,hsaw og ot gniog uoy era ,hu oS“ .ruf
,sregnif sih tsap tuo dekael muC
.niks reh revo decnad noitapicitna gnilgniT
kcoc s'ivA fo driht a ees ot dekcohs saw allaC ,nwod gnireeP
?aedi doog a s'taht erus uoy erA“
.reh edisni deslup kcoc siH
!daer ot skoob thguorb I
"?kniht uoy t'nod ,sessap eerht ,owt rehtona naht erom ekat t'ndluohS“
.stit ym revo ,ecaf ym revo lla ti rettalps ,ivA ,tuo lluP“
.dne s'ivA morf hguorht emac traeh rehtona
,ti dnuora ruf eht hguorht gnilggirw
.ylleb sseltrihs dna mra sih neewteb desserp saw ehs sa
.spil yssup reh revo nwod dna
.reh nihtiw reduol dna reduol demmurd erusaelp fo borht llud ehT .gnar srae reH
.oopmahs reh tsap muc fo llems tniaf eht tuo kcip reven dluow eson namuh a tuB
.elohliat reh ta gniloop ,ruf reh hguorht
,emit siht ssik eht ekorb allaC
.elohliat reh tsniaga deppals sllab siH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
tropria nmad siht ni eno ylno eht saw ivA
.ti rof pu edam thgiled raelc s'ivA ,revewoH
.llew sa taht dnes dna
.eciov sih ni feihcsim ,deksa ivA
.gninrom litnu toN .on kcuF“
.sinep kciht s'ivA revo ti esae ot wam reh detrap ylluferac ehs
.yssup ydeen s'allaC ot ecnartne eht tsniaga nwod dekcud
.ruf reh otni tuons reh deffuts ehs nehw
",ivA ,flesruoy tuoba yrrow tsuj uoY“
",ivA ,nomékop gnikcuf a m'I“
.tsehc yzzuf reh ot enohp reh degguh dna derevihs ehS
.sdlof dekaos s'allaC gnola nwod detfihs sregnif siH .niaga desuap eH "—
.thgil htiw hsulf niaga ecno saw
emos htiw edam ehS .etag reh ot decar ehs sa taeh htiw gninrub ydob elohw reh
.suovren tsuj m'I .erus m'I ,od uoY“ ".fo
.namuh a htiw xes dah reven ev'I“
,yllufyalp delbmur eciov s'ivA
,dnah sih fo pot no detser wap reh ,llitS
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sgnignoleb reh tcelloc ot moor letoh eht ot denruter ehs ,gninaelc retfA
.allaC ,yssup ruoy em wohS“
.eciov reh fo tuo enihw a peek ot elbanu ,dias allaC
.tsal nac I gnol woh wonk t'nod I ,tihs hO“
.yssup s'allaC dnuora delriws sregnif siH
"!muc ruoy htiw yssup leziub elttil ym llif esaelp
.pop a htiw mih ffo htuom reh dellup allaC
.em no detrats uoy gnitniap siht hsinif uoy litnu toN
.ecalp fo tuo gnitca nomékop evisarba na sa reh was tsuj snamuh ynam os nehw gnimrahc dna trams dna ynnuf reh dnuof dna
.siht rof llams oot tib a er'uoy ebyam kniht I ,hu I“
eno siht piks esaelp
.dne eht no dekcat saw ijome traeh rehtonA
.ti tnaw uoy ekil dnuos t'nseod tahT .ivA ,oN“ "—ecin eb d'taht
sliat reH .tih msagro reh nehT
.reh ta nwod ylgnivol dezag eh nehw
.taeb gniworg taht fo pot revo dekips taht erusaelp esnetni na htiw reh detloj dna tilc reh ta debbur regnif tsrif ehT
.suoicsnoc-fles rehtar demees eH
.tsyrt oobat rieht ta tnih ylgums
,sregnif tfos rednu ylbarusaelp gnilgnit niks evitisnes ,ria looc—
,ffo enohp reh denrut ehs erofeB
,steehs eht rednu ,erehT
",uoy fo dnik os s'taht ,allaC ,nimyahS teewS“ ".namow
.revol reh htaenrednu morf tuo thgir reh gard dluow erusserp ria eht deirrow ehs drah os nups dna steknalb eht fo eerf ekorb
.noitasnes fo snoisolpxe htiw reh edisni gnipmup deunitnoc kcoc siH
,niaga tilc reh revo deregnil sregnif sih sa denaom ehS
.reh hguorht dehsulf niap fo tnerrucrednu gnitib a htiw dexim erusaelp fo hsur a ;delaeuqs ehS
,htooms os erew sregnif siH  2 fo 2 traP
.erusaelp reh gnitingier
.rood eht ta dessarrabme ecnalg eht dah ivA
revihs s'ivA tlef allaC ".ti
.ydob reh otni tigid eht gnidnirg
,uoy tem tsuj I
.won thgir lla uoy fo kcis gnikcuf yltsenoh m'I
,meht dias ivA yaw eht ebyam ro ,sdrow eht tuoba gnihtemoS ".uoy
"!thgit gnikcuf os er'uoY
,allaC si sihT ,depyt ehS
.allaC morf pleh yna tuohtiw ,ylisae erom
.sllaw reh tsniaga deggard
.ti rof krow gnikcuf uoy ekam annog m'I tuB“
wap llams reh ni dluoc ehs tahw detser ehs tub
,revo koot erusaelp fo sevaw gnihsarc eht taht borht hguone llud a ot dedaf niap eht nehT
.yaw gnorw eht ruf reh gnitrap
.reh edisni tif evah dluow
.yawa selbuort rieht deklat yeht erehw
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
eguh os tlef regnif siH
.steehs eht tsniaga drah gnipmuht dna
,tnenimorp erew spil siH
,ereh ees ot deneppah enoyna fi ,lleH
,nihc sih fo egde eht tsniaga pu elzzum reh hsup ot detsiwt allaC ".noitcetorp
.citarre werg gnitsurht s'ivA ,citats gnilgnit
,nwod meht decrof yllanif dna steehs dekcut yletanitsbo eht deppirg eH
.taes wodniw reh otni nwod delttes neht dna
.tuo meht gnikcehc nehw ecnalg a allaC dna ivA deraps ylerab eno sihT
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.erac t'ndid allaC tub ,draehrevo eb ot hguone duol tsuj sdrow dna serats erew erehT .elzzum ot spil
.tilc dedooh reh revo elggirw ot pu emac ti litnu yssup reh dnuora pool a gniggard
lluf os tlef ydaerla ehS
.htuom nepo dna seye ediw etuc s'namuh eht ta pu gnihctaw
.erusaelp fo segniwt gnildeen elttil eht morf gnihctiwt ,deredduhs ehS
,niaga dnah sih ta dehsup allaC
.worb a gnisiar ,deksa allaC
.ydob s'ivA gnola nwod leziub eht detfihs sdnah gnorts ,mriF ".allaC
.llew sa reh ta nwod gnirats saw eH
,reh ot txen tas namuh a ,ylikcuL
.niaga os od ylippah dluow ehS
,dnuora erew nomékop yna fI
.namow a ekil leef em ekam uoY
.taht yb desirprus t'nsaw allaC .tsrif ta truh tI .denaorg ehS
.niaga uoy ees ot tnaw I .nooS“
.sesnes reh derewoprevo muc fo rodo yksum ,ygnat ehT
,pirt eht fo tuo emoc dah taht ecnayonna dna noitartsurf eht lla roF .taht wenk ehS
noitaralihxe fo sehsur elbatciderpnu eht morf detfihs erusaelp s'allaC taht tnaem hcihw ,raluger werg gnitsurht s'ivA "!kcuF .ti ekil erom s'tahT“
wonk uoy dna ,yldlrow dna ,decneirepxe os mees uoy ,naem I !tsuj I“
.sthgilf gninrom rof noitaraperp htiw deltsub sllah lanimret ehT
,sdlof dna aibal reh revo gnibbur dna gnizeeuqs ot denruter sregnif siH
.tsehc s'allaC ni dedolpxe seerfrettub fo rettulf A
.doog sleef taht ,kcuF
.erised htiw dliw reh edam tI
.yssup evitisnes reh fo hcni yreve gnirolpxe
,gnibborht fo murht gnisir ,reidaets a ot
.deppilf hcamots s'allaC
!reh ees emoc ot desimorp d'eh taht
.sevlesmeht eerf ot gnilggurts
.steehs eht ni elcric pmad elttil a tfel tI
.avilas reh htiw dexim dna
.namuh eht ta pu gnizag ,denaom ehS
,deooc ehs sa seye reh ni erised luftsul
dnah rehto sih taht reh dlot htrof dna kcab gnilffuhs thgils sih dna mra sih fo gnisnet eht ,yssup reh edisni deyats regnif eno hguohT
"!em detlih ev'uoy litnu muc erad uoy t'noD“
.dias eh ",hguoht ,ekas ym rof teiuq yats t'noD .thgirlA“
mih htiw thgin taht tub
.ijome traeh rehtona tnes ehS !noos klaT
"?taht ekil em gnisaet retfA“ ".dab
.hcaeb a no edit eht ekil reh revo dehsaw erusaelp fo hsur A
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
,sgel ym neewteb ereht nwod teG
selaTiuB emannep rieht rednu sdlobok dna nomékoP tuoba setirw ohw
,yawa ylidaets werd tI
,xes fo dekeer moor ehT
.siht gniod er'ew taht ,llew
ylleb reh no muc fo raems a hguorht deppils sregnif siH ".thgir
.hcaer dluoc ehs sa raf sa saw hcihw
,rettOtnacifingiS yb ”yaL-
.pit kciht eht ssik ot ni denael ehS
,htiw dezzub enohp reh erofeb dessap sdnoces net yleraB
.reh edisni yllufrednow gnilruc tpek regnif s'ivA
.reh ta nwod neht ,ti ta dekool eH
,niaga enola tsomla tlef ehS
.spil sih tsap yrtne gnicrof ni emit on detsaw eugnot s'allaC
.detats allaC ",uoy llet d'I
.meht edih ot ruf yna tuohtiw skeehc der teeb nwo sih ffo wohs ot gnivah nam roop eht rof dab tlef ehS
sbun elttil eht dnuof eh emit sihT
.smoortser dna ,spohs ,stnaruatser
.liat reh fo esab eht dezeeuqs dna kcab reh dekorts dnah s'ivA
.srevoc eht ni dnuora detsiwt allaC ".ekil
.ti tlef ehs emit siht dnA
erusaelp htiw dekraps elppin A
.htaerb fo noitalahxe prahs a hguorht dias ehs
,gnorw ylsuoires si gnihtemos sselnU“ .derepsihw ehs
.tuons mraw reh tsniaga dehsup spil siH .deilpmoc ivA
flesmih detfihs ivA .taht dekil ehS
.htaenrednu gnilgnad kcas ytfeh sih
.allaC otni deremmah neht dna kcab werd eH
.enog ti tnaw ylurt t'ndid
.spil yssup reh neewteb kcoc sih dnuorg ivA
.noitcartta lautum a derahs owt eht taht dezilaer ehs ,erehT
pihsrosnops s’namuh a gniriuqer
,dehsulb eH "…allaC—
"?naem ot desoppus taht si tahw yltcaxe dnA“ "?yllaeR“ ".namuh
.reh edisni peed gid ot drawrof delruc regnif a sa
.tnecs namuh ,enilucsam ,lufrednow sih ekil
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ivA namuh a htiw detaresimmoc
.yob ,kciuq nrael uoY“ .dehgual allaC
,tuo mih pleh ot nwod dehcaer allaC
gnizzub ylelituf
.edis rehtie no gel a htiw gnileenk
.ecrof lluf reh tih xes esnetni fo stuob ynam ,ynam rieht fo hcnets ehT
,ti derolpxe wap reH
kcoc sih fo pit eht ta delkcus ehs ylluferaC
.sdrow rof delggurts eh sa
.toh os saw tahT !on kcuF“
.lla retfa ,nekat reve d'ehs elam tsegral eht saw eH
.mraw dna lufrednow saw rewohs ehT
".sruoy fo elzzum yxes taht lliF
.rovalf yksum eht devol ehs dnA
.regnol koot yllausu selam thguoht I“
.dezzub enohp nwo reH
.niaga kcab spih sih ward t'ndid eH
.meht tsniaga guns desserp pit siH
,nips ot delggurts sliat reH
.ffo llup dluoc I hsiw I taht ecnaifed dna ecnedifnoc fo ria siht evah uoY
.sdrawnwod tfahs mraw taht gnilgna ,detlit ivA
.rettib dekil allaC tub ,oot rettiB
.dab denmad os sruoy deen I tub ,kcid a eb thgim I !esaelP“
,ssik doog nmad a saw tI
enoyreve llet ot detnaw ehS
,mih txet dna no kcab enohp eht nrut ot dehcti sregnif reH
,hteet reh dettirg ehS
.reh edisni gnidliub ysatsce lluf
.elzzum reh tsniaga kcab yletanoissap dehsam spil sih ,nehT
reh fo edam eh ssem eht gniye ylraelc ,dias ivA ",yrroS“
.aes gnihsarc ,citoahc a ni retaw eht evoba daeh reh peek ot gnihsup
,dessik meht fo owt eht dna