dednuos eltsihw llud A
",ylimaf a rof emit fo ytnelp evah lliw I
sffilc eht gniees fo tcepsorp eht ,taht etipseD
",mmM" "?pu dnuorg eht morf ssenisub sih tliub dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,elgooM goM yb
.edirb wen sih ot txen gnidnats
”poT eht revO“ saw sihT
.flesmih ot delims dna daeh sih koohs llewoL
,seye sih gnisolC
.scissalC eht gniydutS .haeY"
.stiucsib wef a htiw rehto eht dna
.elbadnatsrednu s'tI"
",aet tsuj ,oN"
.elibomotua eht fo tuo deppets dna revo dils nameltneg redlo na sa sserd reh denethgiarts ylfeirb ehS
mroftalp eht fo kcab eht ot deklaw eh sa dehcterts llewoL
elfir sih fo dne eht ot ti dehcatta dna tenoyab sih werd eH
"?uoy rof rotius a eb thgim ereht tub
,elbat eht no meht tfel dna seinnep wef a tuo dellup
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots s’goM fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.t'nac yllaer I ,oN"
.efac eht fo tuo ennA detrocse eh erofeb yart revlis eht no meht gnivael
,ni lla ti koot llewoL
".yliratnemom gninruter eb lliw hpesoJ
reh rof rood eht dleh eH
..." .retto gnuoy eht tuoba erom wonk ot dah eh dna
ssap ot egairrac nward esroh a dna elibomotua na rof detiaw eH
sserP lesaeW morf  traeH s'efiL fo stnemgarF ni dehsilbup tsrif
# .emit tsrif eht rof rehtegot desserp spil riehT
.ytuaeb reh yb dezama saw llewoL
slloR fo tnorf eht dnuora devom llewoL
.ennA ,yaw taht eb t'noD"
.seitfif etal sih ni eb ot deraeppa tub ,desserd-llew a saw eH
,flesmih tcudnoc niaga ecno dluoc eh erus ylbanosaer saw eh nehW
.taht ekil ton s'ti ,on ,oN"
.kcen sih fo kcab eht debbur eh sa dias llewoL
elttil yrev morf emac eh woh tuoba sklat syawla ohw nam eht morf gnimoc siht tub
",uoy knaht ,aet emos tsuJ"
”poT eht revO“:yojne esaelP
".sdnabsuh nekat evah sretsis ruoy htoB
.yas retto redlo eht draehrevo eh
ot uoy hsiw t'ndid I detirehni uoy s'rehtom ruoy fo gniht ylno ehT
.ekac reh fo etib dezis-elbbin a nwod dewehc ehs sa desuap ehs
.emit eht evah t'ndluow I diarfa m'I"
,gniraehrevo rof em nodraP"
.mih ta pu dekool dna dias ehs  ",erus ton m'I"
.taht ekil ton s'ti wonk uoy ,tseraed woN"
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
,ssel on teerts eht no nees tsuj d'eh regnarts latot a dna
.elims a dah sserd etihw reh ni retto retrohs eht
.yllis elttil a leef did
,efac eht ta neht
",t'ndluohs yllaer I"
.reh ta nwod dekool eh sa deksa llewoL
.noitnetta sih debbarg selibomotua eht fo eno nehw teerts eht pu yaw flah saw dna
,setalp llams owt dna spuc owt htiw top aet a
.mih fo daetsni ekac reh no erom sucof ot deunitnoc ehs sa deilper ehs
"?yas ew llahs ,ffo llew ssel yllaitnatsbus
.delims dna dias ehs
,tekcaj tius loow sih fo eveels eht no gnitser
.esuolb mrofinu sih rednu ti gnikcut erofeb ti dessik dna tekcol eht desolc llewoL
"?llorts a rof em nioj uoy dluow"
.won evael t'nod I fi gniteem ym rof etal eb ll'I ,hcihw fo gnikaeps"
etag nori detniap neerg eht hguorht dna
".roivaheb edur ym rof ezigolopa I
,rethguad sih saw ehs oS
elbat ytpme eht ot deunitnoc eh
.ydalim ,seigolopa yM"
.htaerb ykahs a werd eh dna
tuo tog revird ehT
.klaw a rof reh ekat ot deksa eh erofeb flesmih decudortni neve t'ndah eH
tius tsenif sih ni retto gnuoy eht fo erutcip dedaf a laever ot nepo saw tI
.deirram erew ew nehw roinuj ruoy sraey owt saw ehs dna ,rehtom ruoy sa lufituaeb sa tib yreve er'uoY
.gnirettalf ti dnif yllautca I tub
.ffo ti devaw neht dna yltfos delggig ehS ".erehwyna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.elbat eht ta owt eht no kcab sucof ot deirt eh sa
.ecaf sih ot nruter taeh eht tlef dna niaga elims reh was eH
,mia laer on htiw daor eht ediseb htaptoof eht gnola gnivoM
dluohs yeht ,noitats emos sah eno esuaceb tsuj taht aedi eht htiw deerga reven I
,rehtaf ,os gniyas rof em nodraP"
,tekcop sih fo tuo seinnep esool wef a dehsif dna
"?uoy era ,mrofer laicos rof yranoitulover a fo tib A" ".yteicos
,emit eht fo sdnert eht etipseD
.reh ot kcab noitnetta sih dellup elggig tfos A
gnorts yrev t'nsi nitaL ym diarfa m'I ,raey-tsrif a ylno m'I
.mih ot kcab s'retto redlo eht htiw nwod tas dna
.aet gnipeets gnorts dna
".enif eb lliw I .rehtaF ,sriaffa ruoy dneT"
.dehgis dna seye reh dellor ennA
mih demlehwrevo ytisoiruc sih tub ,od ot gniht ylnameltneg tsom eht neeb evah ton thgim gnippordsevaE
,seye reh desolc ennA dna nwod denael eH
,aet sih gnirongI
.ecaf sih no elims a tpek
renniw drawa oeL 8102
.tnemom a rof seye dekcol dna
ylsuoiruc mih ta pu dekool ennA ".ot
.edis eht ot daeh reh gnikcoc
.enihs hgih a ot dehsilop ti tpek erac gnivoL
,tekcop tsev sih morf dellup d'eh hctaw tekcop ssarb eht fo ecaf eht ta dekool eh sa derumrum eh
mra sih rednu dekooh saw wap etaciled reH
,puc sih ni aet eht dehsinif eh ,taht htiw dnA ".eciffo
.serutaef tnenimorp erom ruoy fo eno si
aet dehcuotnu sih htiw elbat sih ta deppots llewoL
.mih fo tnorf ni nwod ti tup dna
,elbat eht morf pu esor eh sa desuap llewoL ",yas ,hU"
.dlot m'I os rO" .deilper llewoL ",tse aitnetop aspi aitneicS" .nitaL tcefrep ni dias ehs ",siga douq egA" ".seroinamuH earetiL
mih ta pu dekool retto gnuoy eht nehw gnippots
.ffo llew tsom eht neeb syawla t'nsah ylimaf ym ,lleW .ees I ,hA"
.meht no ni netsil ot tseb sih did dna owt eht drawot srae sih dekrep eH
.kciwsihC ni sa segairrac dezirotom ynam sa ylraen htiw sdaor eht ees ot retto eht desirprus ti
.retto eht fo serutaef eht ni knard daetsni eh
.daeh sih koohs llewoL
.ffo delb ti sa niart eht fo tnorf eht morf dessih maetS
.swap sih ni tekcol depahs-traeh dlog eht dehctulc eH   elgooM goM yb
.ekac egnops lufrednow a ekam yehT
.rood eht denepo dna edis bruc eht ot dnuora deklaw dna
.htaptoof eht no htob erew yeht nehw niaga mra sih dereffo neht
.enil eht nwod deohce "!stenoyab xiF"
"?thgir lla uoy erA" .emit tsrif
,noonretfa eht naht erom yats ot snalp on htiW
"?tneduts drofxO nA"
,enoemos truoc dna yrt ot detnaw eh taht noiton ehT
,meht drawot kcab deklaw eH
.daor kcirb eht dessorc neht
.ffuD rednaxelA fo nisuoc tnatsid a m'I ,yldesoppuS
".yrt a ti evig dluohs uoY
.erats yllamron t'ndluow I"
.sregnessap gnivirra rof
.mra sih rednu wap reh dekooh dna
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
",ssim ,nodrap ruoy geb I"
.yteicos fo tser eht evoba latsedep a no dleh eb
.rood eht tuo dna llewoL tsap deirruh dna riahc sih morf esor neht
.yltfos dias ehs ",gnirats erew uoy taht eciton tub pleh t'ndluoc I"
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
dias ehs ",ennA m'I
eht rof reviaw noisserpxe reh was eh
"?evol ni llaf uoy nehw ekil leef ti seod tahW"
.yawa ezag sih dellup eh taht
elttil a sleef egairram a htiw pihsrentrap ssenisub ruoy gnitnemec ,sediseB"
.os gniod saw eh taht suoivbo ti ekam ot ton gniyrt
.delims dna dias llewoL ",uoy knahT"
ezag sih werd tsuj taht ega sih retto rehtona nees reven dah eH
,yart revlis a htiw sretto owt eht ot revo tnew revres eht sa dehctaw eH
seirtsap dekab hserf fo amora eht htiw deteerg saw eh
.rehtaF ,won tnereffid elttil a era semiT"
".etilop dna emosdnah osla er'uoy tuB"
.rotius laitnetop a saw ereht tub
,morf emoc dah eh noitats eht drawot nwod
.enoemos htiw nettims yltnatsni os neeb reven dah eH
tca eht ni mih thguac dna pu decnalg ehs nehw ylno saw tI
".oot ,hsilop elttil a esu dluoc noitaicnunorp ruoY" ".tey
.bruc eht ot nwod deppets ydal gnuoy eht sa dehctaw llewoL
.pu daeh sih dekrep llewoL taht tA ".gnirettalf
".drofxO ot og I detsisni apap ym taht hguone s'ti tub ,gnihtyna naem yllaer t'nseod tahT
".ennA ssim ,laiceps gnihtemos yllaer er'uoY"
.mih koohs ecnalg a tsuj morf kcaba nekat ylneddus gnieb os
.yawa dekool ehs sa dias ehs
.ria eht detaemrep esaerg enigne dna sreliob derif laoc eht fo llems ehT
",egairram redisnoc ot gnuoy oot ma I ekil leef llits I ,rehtaf ,tuB"
riahc reh mrof esor ehs sa elims a ot dednetxe nirg s'llewoL
...erew ew dna gnuoy saw I nehw ekil saw ti tahw rebmemer tsuj I
.regnarts a htiw srettam lanosrep ssucsid ot reporpmi eb dluow ti kniht I ,llew ,seY"
.ekac reh fo setib dezis elbbin erom wef a koot ehs sa ydal gnuoy eht ta kcab dekool eH
,teerts eht pu dekool eH .dah ehs yaw eht
.llaw kcab eht raen elbat a ta ni gnilttes
.efac eht fo tnorf ni htaptoof eht otno pu dna
.tiaw dluoc revoD fo tser ehT
.delkcuhc neht dna
.reh morf ssorca retto redlo eht ta kcab dna
.erehwyna og ot ydaer teg ot sega uoy sekat tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
si yrots s’yadot dna
"?kniht uoy t'nod ,ciahcra
.gniklaw deppots ehs sa mra sih tsniaga gut reh tlef eH
".llewoL si eman yM
.daeh reh koohs neht delkcuhc ennA
.reyarp kciuq a htiw delahxe dna ni dehtaerb eh
.ekatsim sih ezilaer yletaidemmi llewoL edam tnemmoc ehT ".regnarts
yawa gnikool erofeb elims elttil a mih evag ehs sa rettulf traeh sih tlef eH
elbat s'ydal gnuoy eht no eno eht ekil yart revlis a htiw nruter nexiv eht deciton ylerab eH
ekac fo ecils llams a htiw eno
,deksa dna llewoL ot pu deklaw norpa reh ni nexiv ehT
retto regnuoy hcum eht ot mra sih reffo mih was llewoL
,sdneirf sih gnoma eruskcoc dna hsarb netfo saw eH
"?ti dluow ,truh t'ndluow dnuora llorts kciuq a ,lleW"
,roiretni eht dnuora ecnalg kciuq a retfA
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
".edaced siht fo dne eht yb dnalgnE ni seilimaf tseihtlaew eht gnoma eb ot enil ni htob er'ew
.detaeh skeehc sih dna decar eslup siH
"?ragus ekat uoy oD" .deilper llewoL
.dehgis eh erofeb dias eh ",sey ,hU"
.efac eht otni reh trocse neht dna
.tah demulp a dna sserd gnol a ni namow gnuoy a ot wap sih dereffo eh ,nepo ti gnidloH
.llewoL ,uoy teem ot demrahC"
# .trofmoc mih thguorb syawla tI
.pot eht revo tnew nootalp sih dna
,ylsuoiruc reh ta nwod gnikooL
.daeh reh koohs neht
,htron gniog senil-liar wen eht htiw ,si drow ehT"
".evresed uoy noitats eht ni decalp ylmrif era uoy erus ekam ot ekil tsuj dluow I
,tfel rehtaf s'ennA sa dehctaw yllausac llewoL
.eciffo eht ta em spord eh retfa pu uoy kcip ot egairrac eht htiw kcab hpesoJ dnes ll'I"
dednuop traeh s'llewoL "?yadoT"
.efac a fo tnorf ni pots stnecca dlog htiw ecyoR-slloR a was eH
.mih htiw egaggul on thguorb dah eh
.mroftalp eht otno egairrac eht morf deppets llewoL
,dedneffo eb ylbaborp dluohs I"
.flesmih esopmoc ot deirt eh sa dehgis llewoL
.ot tnaw uoy taht snaem tahT !ah-hA"
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.reh ediseb elbat reh ot revo deppets llewoL
",fao yllis a er'uoy dnA"
.elims teews dedda na htiw
.lairetam eht hguorht neve saw dap reh tfos woh leef dluoc eh nrows evah dluow eh tub
"?uoy rof teg I nac tahW"
",dnabsuh doog a ekam d'eh tsurt dluow I dna ,emosdnah etiuq yllautca s'eh..."
'.seidalim' ynam oot diova ll'uoy epoh I dnA"
ylevissimsid tub yletilop dias llewoL
,tsacdop weiveR ruF pU fo tsoh-oC dna
.nirg yoc a htiw mra sih dereffo dna tuo woble sih dednetxe llewoL ".t'nac
.teparap eht decaf dna dnuora denrut eh sa
.sruoh eerht tsomla rof mih dniheb delruc neeb dah taht liat sih dna sgel sih gnihcterts eb ot yppah
".uoy llet ot elba eb t'ndluow I ,yadretseY"
nameltneg redlo dna ydal gnuoy eht was eh
nwot fo retnec eht drawot denrut eH
.daeh sih koohs dna delkcuhc llewoL
,ni gnippets dna rood eht gninepO
,elgooM goM yb ”poT eht revO“
.niaga efac eht ta neht dna