.os erom ton fi ,saw ehs sa depmarc sa eb ot dah namuh eht ,esruoc fO
tsehc reh tfel dnah sih neht tub
.spuc citsalp elbasopsid owt otni ruop ot ti detlit ivA
.riah nworb fo pom a htiw gnuoy dna llat saw eH
.dias allaC ",ivA ,ereh pu kcuf eht teG“
iuB thgilF thginrevO“
,htuom reh fo tuo gnimoc erew taht sdrow eht dezilaer ylluf ehs erofeB ".haeY“
.noisserpxe knalb a htiw
.noisserpxe yraelb a htiw dehcaorppa allaC
.neddih-llew saw hsulb yreif reh taht dalg yrev saw ehS
,yeh dnA !ti tuoba yrrow t'noD“ ".riah
,reh htiw detaresimmoc ivA sa ,nehT
.yldneirf neeb dah yug ehT
,htooms reh hguorht gud sregnif sih sa kcab reh decra
,taorht s'allaC ni neddibnu esor lworg A ".eno
.raed ,gninrom eht ni eniN
.romuh fo esnes yrd reh deyojne neve eH
.truh fo tros taht ,nosaer emos roF ".sraey
.yaw eht yb ,ivA m'I
.derevihs allaC ".haeY“ .esuap A
.oot delkcuhc ivA
,ti tuoba skrej erew emos ,erus dna ,pirt siht fo thgin nmad yreve
.taes enalpria llams-oot a otni dehsiuqs
,stnioj doof tsaf eerht
.edud lufthguoht dna looc yllaer a saw ivA
,noonretfa ylrae eht ni tseisub erew sthgilF
.dlrow eht fo strap nredom erom eht dniheb sraey ytfif gal ot demees taht nomékop sdrawot sedutitta rieht morf yawa raf eb ot ydaer naht erom saw ehs
.erofeb sraey net morf elyts fo esnes a dna riah hsinworb htiw namuh dega-elddim a saw retnuoc eht ta namow ehT .nwo reh no
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
hsulb suoiruf a htiw dezilaer ehS
.noitartsurf reh detcelfer evah ylniatrec dluow yehT
.moor nmad a tnaw tsuj I“
.raeh ot reh rof hguone duol tsuj ,derettum eh
dezilaer dna spih reh detfihs ehS
,taem yretsym dna ,egabbac denrub-rezeerf
sletoh ni deyats ev'I
.roolf eht no peels ot deen t'nod uoY“
.sruoh thgie rehtona rof kcab eb t'now dna eciffo eht fo tuo era syug ecnanif eht dnA
".yrros ,nimyahS teewS .thgiR
,yldrieW .deddon allaC ".gnitsuahxe eb tsuM .dlihc a er'uoy ekiL
.ecaf reh ffo pu thgir nesir evah dluoc sworb s'allaC
.sserttam eht tem srevoc eht erehw erusserp thgit eht morf kcab gnivom
,won thgir lareneg ni snamuh tuoba saw ehs sa yrgna gnikcuf sA
,desuap ivA "?esaelP“
.elims dessarrabme na htiw daeh sih gnikcud
.staet fo wor tsomreppu reh ot meht gnidiug
,ot klat ot ecin saw eH
trihs-t sdnalsI egnarO na htiw nam a
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
elgna drawkwa eht morf elttil a dehca redluohs reH
.gnidael os dnuos t'ndluow taht yas ot tahw tuo erugif ot gniyrt ,detatiseh allaC
,eciov teiuq a ni
.egnuol eht ot ffo gnimrots dna
.gnicneirepxe fo erusaelpsid eht dah ydaerla allaC eeffoc elbirret esohw efac a dna
.worromot tuo gnikcehc ,moor enO“
,htdiw roolf fo teef owt naht ssel saw deb eht ot txeN
retnuoc eht morf stnemucod reh gnipiws erofeb etunim a rof gnirettups doots ehs
htuom reh morf tips ot denetaerht taht monev eht dewollaws ehs ,tuo hsal ot detnaw ehs sa hcum sA
.erom sruoh rof nam siht ot gniklat peek dluoc ehs taht gnileef eht dna
moor eht rof dengis ivA retfA
.deb roolf tfihsekam sih ni tif ot flesmih detrotnoc ivA
.retsaf elttil a taeb traeh nwo reH
.yawa decnalg neht dna ,kool gnigduj
.tenalpruF yb 9 gnaF sa hcus seigolohtna ni dehsilbup neeb sah dna
.edaf ot detrats tnev ot egru reh
.ti deredisnoc allaC .deksa eh
.sdne owt otni tilps ti erehw tnioj eht htiw delddif dna
seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
.reh hguorht dehsaw gnignol nedduS
"?thgir ,kcid a tahW“
.kcen sti dnuora liof eht depparwnu dna
.selppin reh rof gnitnuh saw eh dezilaer ehs
,ynit a sa devres tI
deviecer ehs tnemtaert driew eht tuoba no dexaw ehs
eht morf citsalp htiw eniw gnikraps eht fo sniamer lufworros eht deppac yehT
skeehc nwo reh gnignit hsulb eht htob dih ylevitceffe ruf ,ti gnimoorg fo skcabward eht lla roF
ssenkrad eht ni nwod kcab gnilffuhs mih fo sdnuos ehT
.ti llifer ot desoppus saw .oC hpliS
.reh dniheb nups ylsuoiruf sliat reH
,nwod deid dah noitasrevnoc eht emit eht yB
,sworbeye sih fo elggaw a htiW
.kcab reh tsniaga traeh gniremmah nwo sih leef ylniatrec dluoc ehs esuaceB
.detatiseh eh "…hu I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.em htiw thgin eht dneps nac uoY
.flesym yb gnilevart gnikcuf m'I ,sey taht uoy llet ot enohp a yb tis ot gniyap m'I ohw
,tluciffid taht ekam dluoc ruf leziub tnatsiser-retaw ,kciht ehT
.nomékop depyt tsohg dniheb scisyhp eht deiduts eh erehw
?gninrom eht ni enin ro ,noonretfa eht ni eniN“
.sdrow sih otni tperc dah tbuoD ".ti
tsuj I ,tsrif taht fo kniht t'ndid I
.stnemucod ym era ereH
.drawotnu gnihtemos gniyrt mih tuoba deirrow t'nsaw ehs
.nwod flesmih rewol dluoc eh os kcab reh dniheb tsuj detfihs neht
.reh deppots nam eht tub ,pat ot nageb dna
,nosrep laer a ekil reh detaert eh ,lla fo tseb dna
.erot ti litnu citsalp eht dehcterts
tsehc dehtolc sih yaw ehT
,tellaw sih otni kcab ti tols ot gnilggurts tnemom gnol yldrawkwa na tneps
tcaf eht ni gnibbur
.sredluohs reh ssorca thgiew eht
"?huh ,uoy rof snamuh tsuj …I“
.roolf reh no hsarc yug siht tel dna yenom emos evas ot truh t'ndluow tI
"?namuh ruoy dna uoy rof krow taht dluoW
.mp73:01 .03 etaG
.pirt eht rof ot og ot dah ehs spooh eht lla retfa der eht ni gninnur saw tnuocca knab reH
.yrros lla ta ton ylraelc
smrofsnart ivA htiw thgin reh woh dnA
etubirtsider ot kcapkcab reh detfihs dna denaorg ehS .oga sruoh nevele ylraen tfel dah loop detaeh dna deb denoihsuc ,tfos reh ot kcab allaC gnirb ot desoppus saw taht thgilf ehT .ma73:01 daer gnikoob eht ,yad sa raelC
,sregnif sih revo ylluferac wap reh delttes ehS
.yawa riahcmra ytpme na enohp sih ta depyt ylsuoiruf nam deriah-nworb ehT
,evom a ekam did uoy fi neve tub ,ysdnah teg ot tcepxe d'I yob tsal eht uoy era ylno toN“
tsehc reh edisni demossolb htmraW
,hu tahT“ "!sroloc dlog erar esoht fo eno rO
.sthgilf rieht erofeb thgir
.eciov nwo reh htiw sdrow nettirw eht ohce t'ndid ehs emit sihT
,denruter dnah siH
",reilrae erots eerf-ytud eht ta siht deggans I ,uoy ykcuL“
.tsehc reh dnuora pu deldduc taht dnah eht htiw traeh gnitaeb reh leef t'ndluoc eh depoh ehS
.dias ehs tahw fo emos tsael ta dootsrednu elohssa eht ,oS
?gnihtemos ro ruf taht tuo hsaw ot deen uoy od …oS“
swap reh otni liat relleporp reh koot ehS .dehgis allaC ".tnaw dluow erutaerc enas ,lamron yna ekil drac tiderc a naht rehtar gniht diaperp diputs siht no dediced ynapmoc eht dna
.enola tropria eht ni ecnarongi suoixonbo eht lla ta dnim reh tsol ylraen d'ehS
,esruoc fo ,ytisomina eht evresed t'ndid eH
.kcen dna kcab reh deneffits sehca weN
.tep nootrac gniklat emos ton
desahcrup I ohw rosnops ym
,enim rosnops uoY .smoor owt rof yap I tseggus ot gniog saw I ,hhU“
.pu kcab elttob eht detlit yletaidemmi ivA
.kcab ym dniheb deit wap eno htiw uoy fo tuo tihs eht taeb dluoc I
.ecaf s'ivA no rorroh eht ta rekcins ot detnaw ehs
.hcuop reh morf feihcrekdnah a deveirter ehs sa dehgual ehS
,yeH“ "—dna worromot kcab uoy yap ll'I
.mih rof saw ehs tew woh tsuj
.thgilf ym dessim I“
.srae reh gninrub taeh eht dna
.tuoba suoiruc os erew uoy lautir namuh ,citoxe taht fo trap tnatropmi yrev a si ecnamoR“
.worromot kcab em yap uoy dna
.mih gnitpurretni ,deksa allaC
.nikpan a htiw elbat eht no deloop dah taht tib eht nwod dettap ehs hguoht
,gnipmarc pu ekaw ot evresed t'ndid eH
!era sgniht nmad eseht thgil woh tegrof I .allaC ,yrros m'I ,tihs hO !hO“ .pu depmuj eH
.trihs ruoy ffo ekaT“
.tsig eht tog llits I kniht I tuB .em no ysae og sdneirf ym sseug I tub ,gnitirw yna deen t'ndid I dias I wonk I .ereht yrroS“
.staebtraeh nezod a flah rof deunitnoc ecneliS
,sey dnA .ereh eb ot thgir yreve evah gnikcuf I ,seY
"…hguoht ,deb eht fo tuo pils thgim I yrrow I
”yaL-iuB thgilF thginrevO“
"?denilced tog ti naem uoy od tahW“
.niaga dewollaws eH
.elttob eht morf esor tsim ypsiW
reh dna reh revo gniooc
,ti rof diap allaC dna
,egnahc od erus semiT
.llew sa retnuoc eht otno mrof noitacifitnedi nomékop dna ,tekcit
"!ekas s'kcuf rof ,hO“ ".txeN
,dlihc a erew ehs fi sa 'esactius elttil elbaroda'
.hctorc sih fo daetsni hgiht sih tsniaga desserp raer reh taht os spih sih detfihs eH
.noitartsurf ni yldliw detalucitseg swap s'allaC ".em no tnuts tihsllub
dnuora kcapkcab sih gnilffuhs ,dias nam eht
.yltalf dias allaC
psag gnikaeuqs A
,tekcit enalp reh derosnops dah yllautca eh taht yfirev ot
.deremmats ivA ",hu—
.mra reh otni gud redluohs tfel s'ivA
.eniw nmad emos deen I“
.retnec eht sdrawot peels ot derreferp ehS
,seitiliba nomékop reh htiw ,sulP
.ybbol hsulp ,llams eht dehtab thgil wolley-nedlog ,eltneG
.hteet reh dettirg allaC ".gnitsurt
.ti delleuq ehs tub
.ylper talf s'namuh eht emac
!kcab reh dniheb deit wap eno htiw ivA pu staeb allaC rehtehw tuo dnif ot
.enihcam gnihsaw a ekil denrut hcamots reH
,elzzum reh denepo ehs nehW
.yadretsey dnepits ym ffo tuc yehT
,llips llams eht fo tsom pu debbad feihcrekdnah ehT ".tnatropmi
.flesreh edarahc eht diova ot yppah saw ehs os ,edacaf yreehc dna elims ekaf a no gnittup t'nsaw tsinoitpecer ehT
.aneythgim reh htiw namow a dna
.2 lanimreT .tropriA lanoitanretnI ailetsaC
.taht ta ti gnivael tuoba thguoht ehS
"?yenoh ,moortser eht morf kcab eb namuh ruoy lliw nehW“
.doow esraoc eht tsniaga yltneitapmi gnippat tpek taht regnif a dna
.noitarapes fo reyal a sa gnitca
.sredluohs reh ni sehca sserts eht htiw depleh tsael ta hcihw ,kcab eht tsniaga depmuls ehS
.tluciffid setag eht ta sriahc eht ni peels edam taht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.neercs reh ta yawa deppat tnadnetta ehT ".gnilrad ,eruS“ ".ailetsaC ot MA 9 .thgilf taht ot em egnahC“
.snoitcaretni drawkwa ,elbirroh dna seye deggod eht lla morf yawa teg dluoc ehs moor letoh a ni tsael tA
.semitemos sehtolc raew I
.deb eht fo elddim eht ni thgir saw ,esruoc fo ,allaC
,otnaK fo doof eht gnitsat dna sthgis eht gniees devol allaC hguohtlA
.tilskcoc yksum s'elam a otni elzzun ot
.ti tuoba skool driew em evig tsuj sklof otnaK
!mrof noitacifitnedi nomékop dilav a evah t'ndid I fi tropria denmad-morkeZ eht ni eb t'ndluow I
.ruf s'allaC otno gnihsalps
.tnatropmi gnihtyreve tsom sedih ruF
.ruf ot egatnavda suoires eno saw tahT
?taoc ruf eulb a no tup ll'I ,egnaro fo daetsni ebyaM
.tnemgdelwonkca dlim a
"?nomékop ot detcartta er'uoY“
.ecneirepxe tropria gnitartsurf reh
skeehc reh fo ruf eht yb neddih hsulf a htiw
.uoy egrahc ot evah lliw ew ,taht retfA
.sraey noillim a ni toN .uoy htiw gnihtyna yrt reven d'I“
gninnirg ,dias ehs
,deb eht fo driht raf eht no steehs eht tsniaga ylthgit dekcut neve ,revewoH
.ezis reh eciwt revo saw eH
.moor elgnis a rof ytnelp s'tahT
.ti ni mrah gnikcuf oN
.avonU ni rosnops etomer a evah I .em htiw namuh a evah t'nod I
eno siht piks esaelp
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.denethgit tsehc s'allaC
.daeh reh revo welf ti fo tsom
.nomékop htiw ylevitceffe etacinummoc ot detnaw ohw elpoep detcartta yllarutan ynapmoc eht nehw neve
ksa tub pleh t'ndluoc ehs
tnemeticxe fo revihs A
.yteixna htiw dehca sredluohs reH
.ksed eht morf kcab retem a doots ehs litnu drawrof deppets dna ruf reh nwod dehsurb allaC
.dehctiwt redluohs siH
.ti llifer yletinifed ll'yehT ?worromot em llib tsuj rO ?ti no tiderc tup
.der teeb dehsulf ecaf s'namuh ehT ".worromot
.ydob sih htiw noitcennoc etamitni hcus fo gnileef eht
.daeh reh koohs ehS
,deworruf worb reH
,luftcepser ,trams
.ppa dapeton a no nwod yltaen dettoj noitalsnart namuh eht htiw enohp reh tuo dleh ehs ,emit emas eht tA .deksa ehs
.denethgit tsehc s'allaC
.ycilop ruo ton s'tahT“
,htmraw eht ni gnilever
,kcab drac eht koot eh
"?reldduc a uoy erA“ .dehgis allaC
.roolf eht no peels ot nam eht gniksa tuoba dab tlef yletaidemmi allaC
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.wollip eht hguorht detarbiv eciov siH .detrats ivA
taoc ruf a fo tnecsinimer saw kcab reh ot desserp
emit txen ni enuT
,yad rehtona hguorht rewop ot dedeen tsuj ehS
.tuo gniretep erew setag neewteb dekcolf taht sdworc lufesoprup eht won dna
ylleb ylacs a htaenrednu kcud d'ehs woh ro
.thgilf reh rof gninrom eht ni pu hsaw rehtar d'ehs dediced tub rewohs a tuoba thguoht allaC .llah eht nwod moorhsaw lanummoc eht ta pu gninehserf snrut koot yehT
.ylleb reh fo ruf eht hguorht detfihs dnah s'nam ehT
ro moc.yrrufoS no selaTiuB sa
,tnemssarrabme laitini reh retfA
!hO“ ".mrifnoc ot llac nac uoy rebmun eht dna noitatnemucod eht si ereH
.secirp otnaK esoht lla retfa moor paehc a rof dnats yletinifed dluoc I ,kool
.nirg a htiw deksa ivA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.gnidnatsrednu saw ivA tuB
.talf ylsselepoh saw eniw gnilkraps roop eht dna
.gnihtemos teg t'ndid I fi uoy llet ll'I
.ydob reh gnirolpxe morf tnaig eltneg eht edaussid dna
.deniamer hctiws eht morf wolg eulb mid a tsuJ
,ekil uoy naC
"!noitanitsed ym ot teg I erofeb ereh siht nepo ot duarf xat s'ti—uoy llet em tel dna ,yob dab a ekil slrig wonk I ,woN“
yawa trofmocsid reh evig dluow taht esion yna ekam ot ton deirt ehs tub
!drac eht no derdnuh owt s'erehT“
,steehs dekcut ylthgit eht tsniaga pawht pawht ot sliat reh desuac taht erised fo tloj a htiw ,nehT
.elkcuhc kaew a htiw dias ehs ",taht otni t'nera uoy fi toN“
.dednuop traeh s'allaC
.egnuol eht ot revo tnew neht dna
!hguoht ,tseb ym od ll'I
hcuop reh ni dracyek s'moor eht dekcut ehS
.ylleb reh nwod gnidils elihw ruf detrap ti woh htiw
*** "?tahw ro ereh fo tuo gnitteg ew era
,tsuj I ?dnim uoy oD .dnim t'nod I ,oN“
,tlas fo detsat hcihw ,socat rieht eta yehT
a hcus llup ot deirt meht fo enon tub
.eno tseuqer ot sthgir ruo nihtiw s'ti dna ,ynapmoc etavirp a er'eW .erutangis namuh lacisyhp a deen I .egaugnal elbisneherpmoc a ni evah uoy snoitseuq yna etacinummoc“
.snamuh yb detanimod erew taht sgniteem gnidnetta fo segnellahc eht fo emos dehcaorb ylluferac ehS
.deppots gnilffuhs ehT
,oga gnol sbmurc ot decuder neeb dah socat ehT
spihsnoitaler nomékop dna namuh gnidrager taht fo ytnelp was ehs—detaicerppa hcum yrev ehs hcihw
.reh morf ",iub leziub iub iuB .iub leziuB“ a draeh ylno tnadnetta eht nehw reisae raf saw txeT
,yltnatropmi tsoM
,dias retnuoc eht dniheb nam eht ",ris ,yrros m'I“ ".moor
,stneilc namuh sih naht tnereffid yna reh detaert reven ohw
,seno derruf yltsom
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.enif s'tI .elbatrofmocnu em ekam ot gniog ton er'uoY“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
?em no doog kool dluow kniht uoy od roloc ruf tahW“
,yppah saw allaC tuB
,hgual a htiw dias ivA "!haoW“
.elppin a dnuora desolc dna taoc kciht
.tropriA lanoitanretnI norffaS eht fo yawllah ytpme ylraen ,til-llew eht otni tuo nam eht del ehs
.drac tiderc a t'nsi siht tub ,sdrac tiderc ekat eW
,revo thgir delppot puc ysmilf tsrif ehT
.yawa deirruh neht ,ti detpecca allaC
.riah ym fo tuo ffuts taht teg dna yrt ot etah d'I
.puc nwo sih dellif ylluferac neht dna
.sgnirps sti ta deggut thgiew s'nam eht sa deniarts sserttam eht ,nehT
.deppots ivA "—hu ,erus rof neht
,detrats eh ",ma'aM“
,ti tuoba thguoht ehs sa ,hguohT .pu dekcuf eh yldab woh tsuj nrael ot gnitiaw fo daerd eht htiw nezorf saw ecaf sih ,daetsnI
,kciuq a nomékop rehto eht tohs allaC
,woW—t'ndid I .hu I .hO“
taht thguoht evah t'ndluow I ,hu ,tsuj I“
.enif s'tahT .esruoc fo smoor owT“
.gnihtolc sih htiw delffuhs dna
,tnemom a roF .ruf reh hguorht
.tug s'allaC gnitsiwt tliug eht pu detehctar
noisiced reh detterger leziub ehT
"?naem uoy od tahW ?huH“
.em ot klat tsuJ .looc s'tI“
.teiuq dna ecaep emoS
.aidem evissergorp-ssel ni
"?kcab ruoy dniheb deit wap eno htiw pu em taeb ot gniog ton …er'uoY“ ".tnaw
.kcapkcab reh no tekcop edis eht otni kcab enohp reh gnikcut
",tsrif rennid reh gniyub tuohtiw ydal a htiw peels tsuj t'ndluohs uoy
.sredro nam roop eht gnivig tuoba ddo tib a gnileef ,desuap
.sevren reh htiw derettulf sliat reH .derevihs allaC
gninrom eht ni eniN“
tnemom siht niur dluoc taht gnihton—
.mraw os ,gib os saw tI
.krad eht ni yllaicepse
.aera gnittis denoihsuc a morf etisoppo tas llaw ssalg evitaroced a yb ffo denodroc sksed fo tes A
.tropria otnaK eht fo llaw eht no dehcrep draob latigid eht ta derats allaC   2 fo 1 traP ,rettOtnacifingiS yb
tnadnetta retnuoc ni-kcehc eht
.sevren reh fo emos yawa hsaw ot
.depyt ehs "?noonretfa eht ni enin ro
,etaredisnoc dna suoituac saw eH
.retal tuo esnir ot ysae eb ll'taht dna ,tib tsomretuo eht no tog ylno ylbaborp tI
peels ot srelevart gnitcennoc ro deyaled rof ecalp decirprevo
,sreihsac deye-yraelb yb dlos sdalas dna sehciwdnas degakcaperp htiw
,noisnecsednoc htiw deye d'ehs ohw reh erofeb nam eht ekil tsuJ
,tropssap reh polp ot pu dehcaer ehS "?hcum woH
.suovren dednuos eH
-yratnemilpmoc etunim-ytnewt a evah ew taht erawa eb esaelP“
"?melborp a taht sI .oN“
.ruf reh tsniaga dnah taht tuohtiw dloc tlef niks reH
.erutats toof-eerht reh etipsed ti tsap ees dluoc ehs ,erehT
.dab taht t'nsaw yllaer aedi sih
.4118 thgilf senilriA navonU gnidaer txet wolley noen on saw erehT
.enin ta worromot thgilf a s'erehT
.tey reh dehcuot yllaer neve t'ndah eH
,reh ta derats dna ereht doots eH
,thgilf reh gnissim fo pot nO
.etilop yats ot tseb reh did tub degnirc allaC .deksa ehs
,raeh I tahw morf tub ,slautir namuh no trepxe on m'I
,gab eerf-ytud nrot
.revo eb dluow gnihtyreve neht dna
"?drah uoy gnikam m'I“
,dias leziub eht ",allaC“ ".yaw
etamitni dna mraw os saw niks htooms s'namuh A
,sevaol tsehserf eht reh evag syawla ohw rekab atynop eht morf daerb yub
?reisae eb d'ti erom steehs eht dekcutnu ew
avonU ni evitatneserper reh gnillac ylduol draug ytiruces gnidnecsednoc a dna
!oN“ "—dna ,suoivbo os s'ti tuB .siht gniksa etah yllaer I ,kcuf …wonk uoY“
kcen reh rednu ruf eht ni deltsen sregnif siH
,retOtnacifingiS yb
.yad eht rof snamuh htiw enod os saw ehS
!yadretsey dah I hcum woh s'taht tuB“ ".owt-
.pih reh revo detser woble sih sa
.detnaw eh tahw derednow allaC
.snamuh rof gniniart noitingocer hceeps nomékop rof etisbew a gnidliub ynapmoc a htiw dekrow yltnecer d'ehS
.koob sih ot kcab denrut neht
.htaerb fo ekatni prahs a hguorht dias ivA "—hO“ "?em gninoopS“
boj etomer reh rof smargorp enilno ta yawa kcah dna
reh dootsrednu eh erus ekam ot toN
.dap eht no ylsuoiruf gnippat erofeb
,mih rof pu tes wollip eht htiW
.hcum oot raf dehgiew ylneddus tI
,ni erew sgel sih sa noos sA
,reh ta dekool eh nehw
"?egnahC“ "—ot deen uoy oD
",erutangis s'namuh ruoy deen ll'I dna ,net derdnuh enO“
.dessap dah sruoh owt tsomla taht dnif ot dekcohs saw allaC
.trihs-t sih fo cirbaf pu-dehcnub eht tsniaga reh gnillup
.repives a erew ehs fi sa
stnemecnuonna daehrevo gniralb eht fo eerf tub
!deen gnikcuf uoy gnihtyreve s'tahT
.kcen sih fo kcab eht dehctarcs eH ".tsig
.diputs gnihtyna yas t'ndid flesreh ehs taht erusne ot tub ,'siub'
.gnitsurt yrev eb tsum eH !namuh ruoy tuohtiw ,nwo ruoy no pirt a tuo gniyrT ?suolevram tsuj taht t'nsI ?allaC …ereht huh
.derettam taht reh tuoba gniht ylno eht saw sretupmoc htiw edutitpa reh erehw
.ffo erow ssensuovren laitini sih retfa flesmih fo dloha nettog evah ot demees eH
.retnirp reh fo tuo dehcni tekcit repap kciht a ,yrenihcam fo gnirrihw eht htiW
"?allaC ,won sthgil eht ffo nrut I fi dnim uoy oD“
.nosaer taht ylesicerp rof yawa spih sih detlit d'eh taht
.od I sseug I ,haey …I“
.reh tsniaga desserp
.swap reh neewteb ti deidaets dna pu kcab puc eht doots allaC ".won tuB
.wap reh otni gnihgual ,dias allaC ",etad maerd s'lrig yrevE“
tsehc erab s'ivA fo htmraw eht litnu ylno
.oC hpliS ta boj s'ivA tuoba deklat dna
,tnemom a rof demuf allaC
,lanimret sih ta deltrats nam A
.sthgil eht ffo dekcilf eH .doots neht dna
?uoy t'nevah ,yad gnol a dah ev'uoy ,uoy sselB !hO“
",gnihtyna gniyrt uoy tuoba deirrow ton m'I“ "—uoy t'nera tuB“ ".ti
"…emit reisae na evah uoy dluoW“
.thgin taht ytnelp dnuora dehsup neeb d'eH
"!sleziuB“ dna "!siuB“ fo tsrubtuo reh ot gninetsil
.haeY“ .esuap regnol A
,gnol owt enil a dah ylno retnuoc tekcit ehT
.boj nwo reh tuoba deklat ,nrut ni ,allaC
,ekat dluohs ti thguoht allaC taht ytluciffid erom yaw htiw
.desuap neht ,detrats ehs "…I“
.hgual suovren a htiw dias ivA
.ruf ym ot llew kcits t'nod sdiuqiL“
thgilf elbatrofmocnu na rof emit ni tsuj ,eros kcab sih
.yug taht kcuf ,erus dnA“
,namuh a yb denorepahcnu tropria eht ot reh evird ot gnilliw eno dnif ot srevird ixat etarapes eerht hguorht og ot gnivah
.t'nod gnikcuf uoy ,oN“
.tnaw uoy fi ysdnah eb nac uoY“ ,dias allaC
.devres gnieb yltnerruc nam eht dednamed
.kcuF“ ".roolf
.drac sih otni yenom erom tsalb ylneddus thgim suecrA fo tca emos fi sa retnuoc eht ta ereht gnidnats
.ynit saw moor letoh ehT
,dnim tsicisyhp-non reh rof nwod ti bmud ot deirt eh sa hcum sA
.pirt lautca eht retfa levart fo yad a saw ereht togrof ynapmoc ym tuo snruT“
.htaenrednu flesmih tfihs yldrawkwa ot ivA rof hguone
.lanimret lanoitanretni eht ni deltsen letoh tisnart ylno eht saw otnaK fo smaerD ehT
,thgilf ym tog ev'I nehw worromot litnu ni gnimoc t'nsi kcehc eht tuB .peels fo sruoh gniteelf wef a dna daeh ym rednu wollip a tnaw I .tniop siht ta sruoh ytnewt rof pu neeb ev'I ,tihS .oot eM .ti teg I ,haeY“ ".teiuq
dedulcni nuf s'yad eht
.detnuoc taht erehwyna toN
?thgir ,rennid rof drac taht no hguone tog ev'uoY
.em htiw deb otni teg tsuJ
,selaTiuB emannep rieht rednu sdlobok dna nomékoP tuoba setirw ohw
elttob eht tuo detsioh eH
.yrros os m'I !yenoh ,hO“
sksoik detaregirfer til-ylmid lareves ot detimil saw tsil taht ,yletanutrofnU
.wam reh depacse
!htiw laed ot niap a fo hcum oot ton s'ti epoh I
.hgual deniarts a htiw dekoj ivA
",raelc eb ot ,hu I“
ffo ti hsinif ot snalp dna ,dnab rebbur a
.gnitfihs yb etairporppani gnihtemos od d'eh ecnahc eht ta deifirroh saw yug eht taht derugif allaC .evom ot ton drah gniyrt saw eh taht suoivbo ti edam mra esnet siH
.ylbbub dna socat paehC“
.yteixna htiw dezzub yeht sa
"?reveohw ,elpoep ,sgniht eldduc uoy oD .peels uoy nehW“
.odoowoduS nmad a ekil ssa sih pu kcitS
,edis reh dnuora depparw mra s'namuh ehT
neht ehS .dias allaC ".trihs
,dna citsalp eht otni sregnif sih gud eh
.niaga enohp reh dekcehc ehS
.pirt elohw siht ssendedaehkciht rieht dna snamuh htiw detartsurf os neeb d'ehS ?namuh a dnA
.nepo llits saw taht tnaruatser a rof tnuh eht nageb dna
.htaenrednu pils dluoc teef sih os
.snoitartsurf pu-tnep reh fo eno tsael ta tnev ot euneva nepo na tsiser t'ndluoc ehs tuB
.nosrep a was eh taht llet dluoc ehs
.gnihtyna yas t'ndid tub noisufnoc htiw reh ta kcab dekool eH
.ni dettub ivA ",wonk I
.edis eno no dnatsthgin a yb ffo tuc saw htgnel eht dna
"?huh ,nac a ni senidraS“
"?ti t'nsaw ,bmud ytterp saw taht
.rosnops ym fo rebmun tropssap dna ,rebmun enohp ,sserdda eht htiw ereht srepap noitacifitnedi nomékop ym evah I
fi ebyaM .edis eht sdrawot lruc dna yrt nac I
,deremmats remotsuc etanutrofnu ehT ".drac
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,deredduhs ehs nehT
nwod deggut srevoc eht ,yllaniF ".enif
.detsuahxe htob erew yehT
".haeY .moor a erahs ot taerg eb d'ti tuB .ot em tnaw uoy fi roolf eht no peels ot yppah eb ll'I .gnihtyna ro trevrep a ekil dnuos ot tnaw t'ndid I ,tsuj I“
yhw wonk t'nod I .woW“
,desiar saw edis rehto eht no flehs egaggul eht tsael tA
.dewollaws ylbidua eH
,gnihtemos ro redniT no dehctam ew fi ,naem I .uoy ekil yllaer I ,naem I !oN“
seye sih rednu sgab thgil htiw gnuoy saw
.deksa yllanif eh "?tahW“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,etorw dna deddon allaC os ,degnahc dah gnihton
thgit seye reh gnizeeuqs retfA ".raed
.yltsag suoesag erom eht dna eyelbas sa hcus nomékop neewteb noitisopmoc ni ecnereffid eht tuoba yldeticxe dettahc eH
.ylwols deksa ehs
".elbatrofmocnu uoy ekam ot tnaw t'nod I
.kcul sih hcterts ot tnaw t'ndid tsuj eh ebyam rO
.owt-ytfif fo ecnalab a gniwohs si drac ehT“
"?neht ,roolf eht no peels ot gniog
.ees ot dedeen ehs sdrow eht otni srebmun dna srettel gniknilb eht lliw dluoc ehs fi sa
llits sliat relleporp reh peek ot thguof ehS
,eniw fo ssalg reh deruop ivA ".eniw
eno koob ot elba t'nsaw ehs taht
.ti tnaem eh taht llet dluoc ehs dna
enohp reh tuo dellup ehS
,edis reh dnuof dnah siH
.yad gnol a hcus retfa ecin dna tfos nmad os deb siht saw nimyahS teewS …tuB .erutats llams reh fo nosrep a rof ereht nwod ecaps fo ytnelp saw erehT
.ydob reh fo tser eht hguorht dehsulf
.gab citsalp a ni delaes eniw gnilkraps fo elttob a gniveirter ot
.noihsuc naht gnirps erom saw taht
.srodirroc thgin-etal eht hguorht deohce pop ehT ".ylbbub
,ylleb reh revo detfihs sregniF .rewol emit siht
,ytiC doowtfirD ni emoh reh ni kcab eb dluoc ehS
,reh rof suoicaps dna dnarg saw deb dezis-niwt ehT
.ylbatrofmoc mih tif ylerab dluow ti neve tub
.sdeb fo egde eht tsniaga pu gnipeels ekil t'ndid allaC .meht fo owt eht rof saw ereht ecaps elttil woh tsuj dezilaer allaC
skeehc reh morf taeh ehT
,rettOtnacifingiS yb ”yaL-
hcuoc a no nwod tas ehS
.rettOgninnuR@ ,rettiwt rieht no denoitnem
.kcab dekrab allaC
.boj reh dna efil reh ni detseretni yleniuneg os detca eH
!deen I gnihtyreve tog ev'I
.roolf eht otno steknalb eraps eht yal depleh allaC
"!ti teg gnikcuf I“ "-
.gnizzub yliratnulovni morf sliat reh peek ot drah desucof ehS
.ecaps llams eht ni tif ot nwod ylthgils daeh dna pu seenk sih dneb ot dah llits ivA tub ,dab ylbirret kool t'ndid ti
.ereh dnuora dekan og tsuj I .revetahw ,oS
neht dna srevoc eht otni flesreh kcut ot denruter ehs ,oS
.redder neve dehsulf ecaf sih sa
,depmarc erew smoor ehT
,sgnileef reh rof yhtapmys deciov ivA sa
.hceeps nomékop gnidnatsrednu ta tpeda erew snamuh emoS
"?eniw fo elttob a edulcni yllausu ti t'nseod ,sruoy fo ecnamor siht ,woN“ ".tuoba
"?thgir ,citnamor era socaT“
.esrow noitacilpmi eht edam ylno noitatiseh reh dezilaer ehs ,nehT
”yaL-iuB thgilF thginrevO“   yojne esaelP
.roolf eht nO“ ",naem I
retnuoc ksed eht ta nam ehT
.kcab rewol reh fo ruf eht delkcit niks htoomS
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,tuo dleh neht pu depyt ehS
"?rof eludehcser nac I tsenoos eht s'nehW
.egnuol ruo esu ot stseug-non rof doirep yratnemilpmoc etunim-ytnewt a evah ew taht erawa eb esaelP“
noitisop otni dekcub nomékop eht sa edis reh revo gnah dluow wap a yaw eht ot desu saw dna
,reh htaenrednu morf wap reh detfihs ehs sa
,oS“ ,dias dna dennirg allaC
.ytiruces dna smotsuc hguorht kcab og ot gnivah tuohtiw
.sserttam elbatrofmoc eht no tuo flesreh yalps
t'nera uoY“ ".enif s'tI
,erofeb puorg gge reh edistuo nomékop wef a htiw xes dah d'ehS
ni daeh reh koohs allaC ".sruoh
.ynnuf tsuj taht t'nsi ,lleW
,feiler ni dehgis allaC
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.doom luof a ni saw allaC tub
,niaga meht gninepo neht dna
.gnikoj saw eh ekil dednuos flah ylno eH
?erofeb sruoh tem d'ehs nam a kcuF ?siht od ot gniog yllaer ehs saW
.yawa setag wef a tsuj letoh tisnart eht ot kcab yaw rieht edam nehT
namuh gnikcuf emos morf erutangis nmad a deen t'nod uoY
.detfihs reh dniheb namuh fo ssam mraw eht ,ylwolS ".kcab
,tauqs a otni pu flesmih detsiwt ivA ".eruS“ .deksa eh
,tsugsid fo tros yna t'nsaw tI
.ecaps mih reffo ot drawrof detoocs ehS
"!ti htiw yako gnikcuf si
rotcurtsni namuh reh htiw prah ecitcarp
flesreh llits ot htaerb a gnikat
.elbatrofmoc uoy tnaw I“
.uoy rof gnihtyreve ngis ot esle enoemos teg ot gnivah enigami t'nac I .zeeG .yrroS“
.ti ekil ll'uoY .ti ekil ll'I
.mih morf detaidar htmraW
.ffo mih gnittuc ,dias allaC ",edud ,kooL“ "—
,tnadnetta eht morf erats detniop a retfa ,yllaniF
.taht no yler t'ndluoc allaC