.MA2 retfa elttil a saw tI
.em rof esuap t'ndid ehs emit siht dna niaga eman reh denaom I
--nwo reh fo tnecs yna ylerab dah ehS
.derudne htob dah ew srosseforp fo yllufetips ekops
,nwo ym fo stsurht regae tub
.gnihtemos ro setunim net yreve ecno ekil deknilb ylno ehs fi derednow I
seye egnaro ediw reh ta kcab dna pu dekool I
".rehtegot 102 ICOS
,yug ko na si niveK ,naem I
.tnemom a rof ereht em dloh dna
,kcid ym fo toor eht tsniaga seiretsym neesnu reh gnisserp saw ehs kool retteb a teg dluoc I erofeB
".deb rof emit s'tI" ,dias ehs dna
na ni nepo kaeb reh htiw em ta gnikool
thgil fo dnik emos ni delenap saw tI
.eniratcen epir a fo hself eht ekil ,egnaro-wolley
sreksihw dna htuom ym dekcil I
.lassimsid a ro noitativni na saw taht fi erus rof nwonk evah dluow I kniht t'nod I
,hu ,hO" ,pu depip I
.krow eht fo tsom enod dah ehs hguoht neve ,derit daed saw I
,gnislup em leef tbuod on dluoc ehS
.gnihtyna yas t'ndid tub ,deknilb ehS
.hctaw ot daeh ym desiar I sa
.yrruFoS no seirots sih fo tsom dnif nac uoy tub
.kaeb kcalb rednels reh htiw dleh ehs taht warts a htiw ssalg lautca na fo tuo der-elprup gnihtemos gnippis
.shgiht reh neewteb espmilg a thguac I dna
.reh nraw ot gniyrt ,dewollaws neht ,depsag I ",araT"
ytiurf dna teews saw tI
.deciton uoy enoemos saw ehs tub
.emas eht reh deksa I dna
,yrraH yb ”tseN s’lwO“
.htraeh kcirb eht no doowerif fo kcats elttil eht dna roolf dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,lliswodniw eht morf gum eeffoc a hctef ot deb reh revo denael ehS
.oooooooh wol a gnikam dna htmraw reh htiw em gnitaoc
",em htiw emoc nac uoy ,thgir llA"
.sreh fo emos knard ehs dna
,lohocla eht etipsed
,srehtaef etihw fo ksam degde-krad a saw ecaf reH
.tsaf oot ,pu tas I
",esolC"  .gnihton gniyas
...mhu ,siht naht retteb semit derdnuh a skool taht ,os ,hU" ,dias I oS
".ebyam ,airgnas siht fo hguone knird I fI"
.esuoh siht tner eW
.'regal' ,mu nasitra enif
'V' ediw a ni nwod emac sworb reh yaw ehT
.nwod gnikool elihw pu em derevoc dna srehtaef dna smra reh daerps neht
.dnuora gniyalp enod saw ehs demees ti
,kaeb reh htiw yltneg rae ym gnineerp yb em desirprus ehS
.ycrem reh ta saw I
.ton yletinifed tsom saw ehs ,lacol a saw I
hcamots dna tsehc reh ekorts ot pu dehcaer I
--pot knat eht tsol dah ehS
.sllab eht evah t'ndluow I yllamroN
.meht evah smoor eerhT"
.swap htob htiw ti koot I dna
.niaga rae ym gnineerp-elbbin kcab saw ehS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
moor dedworc eht hguorht yaw ym dekcip I
.reh otni gnitrups dees tnedor suoipoc ym
.mottob reh bur dluoc I litnu resolc reh gnillup
.deb reh no reh ot txen nwod tas neht ,dereggats I
.seye reh ot noitnetta eht lla gniward
,nwod desserp dna mhtyhr reh deppots ehS
.gnihsiw dna gnihctaw fo daetsni ,ecno rof reh ot klat ot ecnahc a em dereffo ti dna
,sgel ym gnilddarts
,tnemom a rof taeh renni reh ot desu teg em tel ehS
,lleW"  "?ytrap ruo tuoba raeh uoy did woH" ,deksa ehS
--lammam a ekil t'nsaw ehS
,em ta dekool ehS
.pu siht wercs ot tnaw ton did I dna
"?doog ti t'nsI .moor ym si ereH"
?hsats ruoy morf emos erahs d'uoy esoppus t'nod I" ,dias I
.em otno nwod flesreh gnisae dna pit ym gnihctac
,dias ehS .dewollof I
?uoy era lwo fo dnik tahw os ,yeh reh ksa ot tuoba t'nsaw I dna ,gnihtyna eb dluoc ti os ,slwo morf wonk t'ndid I ?naisA htuoS
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.yawrood raer a sdrawot nehctik eht dessorc ehs sa
,derewsna yllufpleh ehs
.ssecorp eht ni em ta srehtaefliat reh gninnaf
,ylwols htrof dna kcab dekcor ehs
.niaga ecno prihc-elggig reh gnikam
,puorg a sa erar taht lla t'nera snaivA
.ti pleh t'ndluoc I tub ,revetahw dna evitimirp lla sdnuos hcihW
.looC .dem-erp ,hO"  .derewsna ehs
.gek eht ni lliws )eerf tub( retsulkcal
"?nhoJ ,serutcip tniap uoy od ,hO"  ".heH .tra rO
,dias dna gum ym desiar I
,sdnuos gniprihc lanoisacco rof tpecxe ecnelis htooms ni devom ehS
.trihs-t dnab diputs ym gniraew llits
.nwod tfos yltsom saw ffur tsehc reH
...hu uoy oD .t'nod I" ,dias I
,seman tnereffid wef a rednu sehsilbup dna setirw ohw
.seot eht fo spit eht ta swalc evisserpmi gnitrops dna delacs dna gnoL
--erofeb reh nees dah I tub
,suoires elttil a kool reh edam
.gninrom eht ni em htiw laed ot tnaw t'ndiD
,tfos dna mraw erew srehtaef reH
roolf eht ot deppoh ehs nehT
.detiaw dna hsawbur tnedor kciuq a ecaf ym evag I
"?ni gnirojam uoy era tahW"
,snaej ym denottubnu dna nwod dekool ehS
".on ,erofeb ereh uoy nees ton evah I"
.dnuora ecim yerg fo snoilliM
.dnuora kcab denrut ehs nehw ecaf reh ot pu kcab seye ym gard ot dah I
.neve ,gniht dneirf-a-fo-dneirf a eb dluoC .ereh swonk eh ohw erus ton m'I
,reh degassam I elihw em tsniaga deldduc ehS
.sriats eht ekil stops ni ykaerC
.trihs eht tuoba erac t'ndid ehS
.detnaw I naht egde eht ot resolc raf em thguorb ti sa
.elahxe hcae htiw dnuos ...oooooooh
",gninrom eht ni krow I"
.deklat ew sa gniliec reh ta gnirats tneb seenk ym htiw kcab ym no gniyl pu dedne I
.delbbab I ",ycavirp ssim I tub
.esolc seye ym tel I
.epahs rieht seno egral eht evag taht seroc ffits eht leef llits dluoc I hguoht
nwod eil ot em dlot dna daeh reh detfil ehS
.gniknird erofeb ",araT ,uoy knahT"
.won rof desolc seye reh
,rewol deyarts dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
",airgnaS"  "?ti si tahW"
,deksa I "?gniog ew erehW"
,tuo kcurts I fi tilps llits dluoc I ,etal saw ti tuB
".rotaregirfer ym ni si elttob ehT .sriatspU"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dael eht koot ehs neht
,seohs raew t'ndid ehs deciton yllanif I
".moor nwo ym evah I
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
"...ro buthtab eht ni ro hcuoc a no sriatsnwod peels og nac I ?og ot em deen
.ti leef dluoc ehs wenk I dna
.ygolopa na delbmum I
",araT ma I"  .deremmats I "...dluohs
.eciov gnos-gnis gnitlil taht ni
.tis ot ecalpyna eb ot mees t'ndid ereht deb eht sediseb dna ,dnuora dekool I  ".erehwyna tis
eno siht piks nac uoy
,moor s'lrig a otni detivni s'eh nehw sepoh elam gnuoy yna tahw gnipoh saw I
.seY" ,denialpxe ehS
dnuos a gnikam tuohtiw pu tog dah ehS
.tsiser ot gniyrt deppots I dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
lwo na ylno yaw ykoops taht ni noitcerid ym ni daeh reh deleviws ehS
.suolaej ydaerla m'I ?elgnis A"
,em otno dna deb eht otno kcab bmilc reh dehctaw I
.kcab reh derevoc taht seno eht fo tsom dih erow ehs pot knat wolley esool ehT
.natraps dna ydit saw ti tsen s'tar laretil tsomla ym ot derapmoC
?thgir ,ecnahc rehtona teg I dluow nehW
.roolf ralimis a htiw ,doow yttonk
dehctiwt liat yM .citonpyh
,tniop emos ta desaec dah sriatsnwod cisum eht fo taeb llud ehT
.lla ta dnim t'ndid I tuB .stsaerb on
,dias dna dnuos kculc gniprihc a edam ehs dna
,rebos neeb dah I fi neve tub
,ylthgils pu detfil dna
,nehctik eht ni saw ehS
.enoyna no ti gnillips tuohtiw nehctik eht ot ti edaM
.gnivrennu saw tI
rae ym deppin ehS  .derepsihw I
,yzzuf tib a dna mraw leef em edam dah eniw ehT
,em pota yal yllanif ehs nehw lufetarg saw I
.sredluohs ym dnuora mra ekil-gniw reh gnipparw neht
.flesreh elyts taht ni kooc ot stpmetta reh etaicerppa t'ndid setamesuoh reH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
fo trohs tsuj erew seye esoht dna em naht rellat saw ehS
.airetefac supmac-no eht tuoba denialpmoc htob eW
.elihw doog a rof teiuq neeb dah esuoh eht dna
.nruter reh nopu detnemal ehs
.nirg fo tros naiva
?wonk uoy ,stfut rehtaef esoht htiw tros eht saw ehs dnA
.dedicednu fo tros llits ,hu m'I
,ecap eht lortnoc ot elbanU
.naf depirts a ekil reh dniheb tuo eralf ot nageb srehtaefliat reh dna
,gnisimorp erom dekool knird reH
.reeb eht naht retteb hcum ,hcuM
,dias dna esirprus ni srae ym dekrep I
,reh was I litnu evael ot gnihcti neeb dah I
,esaelP .esuoh dlo na si tI
,peelsa ylluf gnillaf saw I sA
.knird reh tuoba deksa I daetsnI
,niveK rof moor eht dnuora dekool I
,erom ecno pu flesreh dehsup ehS
,spih reh dloh ot tuo swap ym dehcterts I
wols htiw reh tem I
.kaep gniredduhs nwo reh dnuof ,oot ,ehs litnu gnipmuh ydaetsnu reh pu tpek ehs tub
,ylteiuq kaeuqs ot nageb I pu deps ehs nehW
,morf saw I erehw deksa ehS
,drawkwa leef ot nageb I dna ecnelis otni despal ehS
.snroh ro srae pu-dekcirp ekil fo tros kooL
,yawllah kcab a otni tuo reh dewollof I os ,kcab kool t'ndid ehS
.pu em dellup ehs dna dnah reh koot I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.eniw reh gniknird dna moor esraps reh dnuora gnikool tsuj
.tnaem ehs tahw terpretni ot gniyrt
,em evah ot tnaem ehS
deb reh otni nwod em sserp dluow ehs suoitcnubmar oot tog I nehw tub
.reh dettops I nehw reeb sseleman fo puc citsalp a gnidloh gek eht yb gniretiol saw I  yrraH yb
.emoh kcab edam ylimaf reh tahw ot esolc neve saw taht ytisrevinu eht raen doof yna dnif ot elba gnieb ton fo denialpmoc ehS
.roolf eht ot meht dehsup dna snaej nwo reh didnu ehS
srehtaef-mra lufituaeb reh ta derats I
.depleh ylbaborp zzub eht dna
.dellihc saw ti hguoht neve nwod gniog eniw ekil mraw dna
neve eciov ym peek ot gniyrt
.airgnas fo elttob eht ffo dehsilop eW
.niaga delggig ehS  "!nmaD
,eson dna sreksihw ym htiw tsehc reh ta delzzun I
.reh edisni peed em gnidloh
.dnuor yltcefrep os ,os dnA
.reh derevoc llits snaej reh erehw ot
.retnuoc eht no nwod puc eht tes dna ",ffuts
,nepo kaeb reh htiw detnap ehS
.epacse ot detnaw taht msagro na fo nrub tnetsisni eht leef dluoc I yspit nevE
.gnola em thguorb niveK etam-moor ym
.tlob ot egru na tlef I dna
.nwod reppiz eht dils neht
.warts reh hguorht pis rehtona gnikat ,dias ehs
tnarbiv a denrub sesiri reH
.enog em detnaw ehs derugif I tuB
daeh ym denrut I
.snolat ekil tib a erew teef reh sa
.airgnas dexim-erp fo guj gib ecin a tuo koot dna egdirf trohs reh denepo neht
evah ew kniht I .nhoJ m'I
.sserttam reh fo egde eht no tis ot devom dna
.gur reh no gnittis regnol on saw ehs deciton dna
yawa debbe enim sa em rof lufniap werg tI
.elzzum ym pu elknirw em edam reeb mraw-won eht fo llems eht tub ,spil ym ot puc ym thguorb I
.suoicsnoc-flah ylno ,kcab reh dekorts dna srehtaefmra reh rednu dehcaer I
.hguoht ,llaw eritne eno pu gnikat ecalperif gib eht ot taes kcab a koot fo dnik lla tahT
.etarucca neeb dah sseug naisA htuos yM
”tseN s’lwO“   yojne esaelP
"?ereh evil uoy naem uoY"
sllaw eht fo doow eht dellems I yltsom
,tfahs ym nwod dna pu gnidils demuser ehs taht fo os ro etunim a retfA .derepmihw I
,em fo tnorf ni dessap ehS
.reh tsniaga revo nael tsuj ot ysae os saw tI .t'ndid ehs tuB
,VT a ,sesackoob was I
.pu ekow I nehw enog saw ehS
.sdnah reh fo eno dereffo dna gnirevaw em deciton ehS
,em revo debmilc ehS
.oot sgel reh dessorc dna revo gur txen eht no tas ehS
,sessalc derapmoc eW
.hsats ezoob desimorp eht dloh tsum taht egdirf mrod eht dna
,ereht yal I sa niorg ym morf pu doots doohesuom gnihca yM
,yawllah krad trohs a nwod deklaw eW
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.enim tsniaga spih reh detaryg dna
,rethgit gnitteg reh leef dluoc I
.did I dna ,dias ehs ",yatS"
...siht fo hguone dah ev'I
.dehgual ylneddus ehs
.pleh eht dedeen yeht taht toN
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.mined eht evoba tsuj detuorps yeht erehw
tnes kaeb prahs reh fo hcuot ehT
",hsats etavirP" .gnirettulf taorht reh no srehtaef etihw ynwod trohs eht ,hgual a derettit ehS  "?ti teg uoy d'erehW
desuap ehs drow a tuohtiW
.dnirg mrif a htiw ekortsnwod hcae gnitautcnup
",ssalg rehto on evah I yrroS"
.reh pots llew yrev t'ndluoc I tub
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.meht desu I dna ,gniog noitasrevnoc a peek ot no kcab llaf nac dargrednu yna snoitseuq dradnats era ereht tuB
.nehctik eht ni puc reeb ym denodnaba dah I ecnis ssalg a em gnidnif ysub saw ehS
...dluohs tahw ,hu tahW ...mhu
.ylisae rae ym hcton dluoc ehs wenk I
.em rof hguone railimaf ytnelp saw taht dna
hctiwt srehtaefliat reh gnileef
,yfmoc dna ecin flesym tog I dna
.citamgine tub gnihtyna saw hcihw
sredluohs ym fo edis rehtie no deb eht no thgiew reh gnitroppus sdnah reh htiW
.tcepxe ot tahw gniwonk ton
.esuom a rof yllaicepsE
".ereh emoc ,nhoJ esuom rooP"
,melborp on yletulosbA"
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ytrap esuoh supmac-ffo-tsuj siht ot em deggard dah ohw
,noitcirf dna taeh eht morf ffits gniworg saw I
.seiduts yrotsih ics-ilop hsilgne laireganam ni pu dne ylbaborP
.ta gnirats diova ylisae dluoc I esohT
.ecalp etiuq t'ndluoc I taht tnecca citoxe na ni ,dias ehs
.nihtiw dessap ehs sa thgil eht no dekcilf dna srood eht fo eno denepo ehs dna
.feiler fo ssilb yvaeh eht deyojnE
.delbraw ehS .depsag I
,niaga ti did I ,degaruocnE
".niaga uoy knaht os ,hguoht emoclew yrev leef I"
,noisserpmi tsrif dab a ekam dluow deb eht rof thgiarts gniog taht derugif I tub
.rettulf smra reh fo skcab eht morf depard taht srehtaef dednab-nworb gnol eht gnihctaw
.deggel-ssorc ,tas dna
",enicidem yduts ot hsiw I"  .deksa I
,kcarc a seye ym denepo I  .dias ehs
.taht ta ooc fo tros gnillirt a evag ehs dna
.llah erutcel eht ssorca ,hgual reh nees d'I tub ,nrets neve
,dias ehs yllaniF
,yreppils dna toh tlef ehS
.deneppah taht nehw wonk t'nod I
,sseug I ,elpoep rehto 002 tuoba dna reH .ssalc ygoloicos ym ni saw ehs
--em no tiaw ot dah ehs erofeb enim fo yletelpmoc flesym dir I erus edam I
.em deciton reven d'ehs derugif I
".sriatsnwod elpoep fo tol a wonk yllaer t'ndid I
,yrraH yb ”tseN s’lwO“ saw sihT
.gnirevocer ,toh dna gnitnap
.dennirg I dna reh morf hgual a tog tahT
eht fo erom gnisu ti evorpmi ot noitacided laer on dna zzub dlim a ylno gnivah
roolf eht gnitaroced sgur latneiro taen eht fo eno dekcip I oS
.dnats thgin reh no kcolc eht ta decnalg I
,moor eht tfel neht
.dekool naem I dna
,neht eman reh wonk t'ndid I
retal werg thgin eht sA
.slwo ynam ees t'nod uoy tub
,em ot ti dednah dna gum eeffoc eht otni emos deruop ehS
?ecalperif nwo ruoy teg uoY"
.hgih taht lla t'nsi esuom a sa hcihw ,thgieh-rae ta puc ym gnidloh
.elims tnedor yreksihw gninniw a saw depoh I tahw reh evag I dna nac
-enips ym nwod dna srae ym gnola selgnit yrevihs
.llah eht nwod gninnur retaw raeh dluoc I dna
,gnineppah saw ti wenk I erofeb detpure niorg ym ni peed ycnegru gninrub ehT
.sriats nedoow worran ykaerc emos pu debmilc eW
.erofeb dekan dna esolc pu eno nees reven dah I dna ,tnereffid elttil a era snaivA