,meht tuoba mih deksa I
.dehgis dna txet a revo dessolg lerriuqs ehT
”.pleh ot gniyrt tsuj m’I
”?elbarenluv eb ot evah I od yhW“
,pu tes krowrepap eht teg ll’I“
”.suovren os eb t’noD
,sregnessap txen eht pu kcip og em teL“
”.llew sa gnikrow m’I os ,deppihs raewmiws ym teg ot deen osla I“ .dias retto eht
?star htiw gnorw s’tahw ,yeH“
.deilper dnabsuh reh
”?edir a evah I naC !notliM“
tcefrep ruoy ffo gniwohs s’noom ehT“
,enigne eht fo raor eht revo gnirps tsal morf sessalc sih tuoba gniklat saw lliB
”.boj wen a uoy gnitteg no krow nac ew yaw siht dna
”.niaga uoy ees ot doog s’tI“ .dehgis eh
.ytisrevinU enakopS morf kcab saw eh dna
neffits kcoc ym tlef I
dluoc I dalg m’I“
,drah si gniklat wonk I
.remotsuc txen eht htiw noitasrevnoc a dloh ot yrt tsuJ“
.gnol os ni neeb dah I tseippah eht tlef I siht etipsed
.taob eht otni kcab em depleh ffilC dna ,kcod eht pota flesym dellup I
”.gnikcuf rof ,naem uoY“
”.sedir eerf tuo evig ot desoppus ton m’I dna
.aisA tsaehtuoS ni spmac eegufer eht ni ekil saw ti tahw tuoba em dlot neht eH
.etatsorp ym tsniaga gnimmals ni kcab dehsup dna tuo dellup eh sa detnurg eh ”,sesirprus evol
”.flesti taob eht otni gnikool er’yeht fi
”.gnivird ton er’uoy nehw rof si siht dnA
.ssa desopxe ym dednuop eh sa kcod eht otni gud swalc yM
,ynnus eht ta elims em edam hcihw
”.no ti yrt ll’I ,yakO“
.meht ni eloh ralucric egral a dah hcihw
”.sboj htob no deniart uoy teg dna
.tolgylop dna ,retirw
”!meht ekam ot ton yrt yletinifed ll’I tub
.eciwt ro ecno ekal eht delcric I sa taob eht ni edir ot dekil tsuj ohw elpuoc xof ylredle teews a erew yehT
,ekaJ“ .dennirg ehs
.egnahc dna emoh ta pots ll’I neht dna
”.nos s’esoR dna eiuoL s’ti
.wap sih ni tekcap erauqs a dna ebut llams a dleh eh dna
”,eurt s’taht sseug I“
sfeiraeB ro srexoF
tuo dekool neht I
,2 fo 2 trap( gnoS lA yb
”?yad elohw eht em htiw taob eht no eb ot tnaw uoy erus uoy erA“
.kcod driht-ytnewt eht drawot gnireets drawrof elttorht eht dehsup dna dehgis I
,mih htiw etad a no tuo tnew
”,wonk I nosrep tseteiuq eht
ekil er’uoY“ .em deknaht eh dna ffo mih deppord I
”…OEC putrats a ekil dnuos ot tnaw t’nod I
,esle enoemos ot gniklat nehw detcelloc dna mlac gniniamer elbuort gnivah er’uoy fI“
.efil sih fo sraey owt tsedrah eht saw ti dna
”?dneirfyob wen ruoy eh si ,notliM“
!ttub ym ffo swohs tI“
”?em sees taob ecilop a fi tahW“
”?htob od ot teg I ,tiaW“
.skeehc ym neewteb pit sih decalp eh sa dias eh
,yvaeh tlef ydob ym elihw
.loohcs hgih ni neeb ev’uoy ecnis elihw elttil a neeb s’ti tub ,trats a s’tI“
”,ecno rof uoy esirprus
.degnid ti dna enohp ym tuo tog I
.evitpircsed yltcaxe ton s’ti ,lleW“
.flesruoy no drah os eb t’nod ,paC ,no emoc ,wA“
.boj dne-daed sih ni llits s’etoyoc eht tub
’,tolip‘ si desu eb dluohs taht brev eht dna
.ylleb sih ot ylthgit em gnizeeuqs gnineve eht otni tuo deirc eh tsurht lanif eno htiw dna
”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“   yojne esaelP
,ekal eht dnuora no ffo trihs ym htiw eussi na fo hcum evah t’ndid I oga sraey wef A
”.tuo elpoep ynam oot eb t’now ereht ebyam
”!hcaeb eht no ffo ti wohs og s’teL“ ”.sknahT“
.em edisni sregnif sih lla gnivohs saw eh fi sa saw ti hcum os nepo em dehcterts daehkcoc eguh siH ”.eituc xaler
.deksa nosliW .srM
triD yb uoy rof daer
tsuj ev’I“ ”?sodeeps ym fo eno gniraew
,ffo trihs ruoy htiw uoy gniees ekil I ,lleW“
.did uoy esruoc fO“  .dias eh
.reel a htiw dias eh
,ffilC rof llef dna
.ti denepo I dna ,modnoc eht em dednah retto ehT
sodeeps fo riap yxes a woh ees s’teL
”,em fo tnorf ni erows yllanif uoY“
htmraw tlef dna
pal ym no rehtegot swap ym tup dna htaerb peed a koot I taes ym ot denruter I sA
.em otni gnikcub elihw ti degassam eh sa niorg ym puc wap sih tlef I
”.esicnoc yrev er’yeht ,llew
em otni desserp eH
.aremac sih no snel eht detcepsni eh sa dias eh
.dezzub enohp reh dna dias ehs
”,eseht otni egnahc ot uoy deen ll’I tub ,oot eurt s’tahT“
.pmuj kcoc ym tlef dna taht ta
ylneddus dna
eht gnivah fo daetsni pag gib siht hguorht pils nac taht
,rehtona eno htiw emit dneps ot teg eW“ .dias ffilC
,lias a tuohtiw tfarcretaw dezirotom a si siht ecnis ,gnilias ton m’I yllacinhcet ,lleW“
tnemrag wen elohw a edam uoY“
”.gnidlocs eht lla od uoy dnA“
,sngised wen pu kniht ot gniht tseisae eht syawla ton s’ti ,haeY“
.tfel eh sa yad doog a elohd dnik eht dehsiw I dna ffilC
,enotirab ylrub a ni delworg eh ”,eituc ,thgit oS
”?ksa neve I did yhW
taob a dehsarc notliM ,emit tsaL
thgil larutan emos rof wodniw elttil a htiw ffo denoititrap aera elttil a saw tI
,pal ruoy ni ro elbat eht fo pot no rehtegot sdnah ruoy dloH“ ”?ti si tahW“
”,seceip lacirotsih
.cirbaf eht morf tniartser thgils a htiw gnola
”’.xes‘ drow eht yas nac uoY .tluda na er’uoY“ .dennirg eH
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.tfel knuks eht retfa dias ffilC
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”,taht ees ot sdeen dlrow eht dnA“
.em edisni pu pmar erised dna taeh eht tlef I sa
”.oot uoy ees ot doog s’tI“
,yeH“ .dehgis I ”,yakO“
.kcod eht fo egde eht otno dleh wap eerf sih dna osrot ym dnuora depparw smra sih fo enO
,deyolpme-fles era uoY“
”.elttaeS ni yrellag tra llams a rof noitisop rotaruc a osla s’ereht ,ees s’teL“
.od ot tahw fo erusnu ereht doots I dna ,dnas eht ot sdray wef a deklaw eW
taht evah uoy did erehW“
.deilper dnabsuh reh
eno siht piks esaelp
,wonk ot doog s’tahT“ .dias ehs
.deksa tiustnap a ni lerriuqs a ”?ydaer uoy erA“
.notliM ,etunim a tsuj em eviG“
”?won thgir egnahc uoy tuoba woh rO“ ”.egnahc
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,taob eht otni sexof eht depleh I dna retto eht devirra ew nehW
,odeeps esiouqrut eht fo kcab eht ffo dewohs eH
.dehgis I ”,thgirlA“
,thgil tlef daeh yM
,cinilc erac tnegru eht ot mih deklaw
.snoitacilppa dna stnemucod suoidet eht no dekrow ew sa elihw a rof noitisop taht ni deyats eW
?serutcip omorp emos gnikat em htiw looc uoY“
.ti evoba gnitniap a dna
egakcap ym puc ot nwod dehcaer eH .ylpeed em dessik dna
”.tuo uoy pleh ll’I .no emoC“
.aremac eht otni kcab dekool I sa mih gnicaf ttub ym fo saw detnaw eh tohs rehtonA
”.snoisacco laiceps ,wonk uoy
,loohcs hgih ni roines a saw I nehw namhserf a sa mih derebmemer I
.semit elpuoc a flesmih dekorts dna odeeps eht morf kcoc sih deerf eH
,ekal eht fo sruot elpoep evig uoy ecnis
gnileef tsetaerg eht tub
.edis eno no nael ti edam yllufesoprup dna
,tliub erusserp eht sa
”.siht htiw pleh dluoc rojam ruoY
”.oot eno gniraew eb ll’I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,gnoS lA yb
s’odeeps eht hguorht skeehc
,nuf eb dluoc tahT“
.eerht-ytnewt kcod no s’nosliW eht saw ti dna ,degnid enohp yM
tnemom a rof ereht deyats eW
.gniddon tpek tsuj I dna
.htaehs ym ni pu em gnirrits tnemeticxe elttil a htiw detiaw dna dedaw I
.ttub ym deporg eh sa dias eh ”,ssa
”?syad wef tsap eht ni
”.kciht adnik m’I
.dias retto eht ”,oga emit gnol a
:dliuG eht morf selaT dna
”.tar a si rats nrop etirovaf ruoY
”.kcab thgir eb ll’I dna ,ksed ym morf gnihtemos teg ot deen tsuj I
”,niaga uoy gniees doog s’ti ,notliM ,hO“
,yad lla stnempihs gnikam em htiw taht od ot gniog er’uoy woh wonk t’nod llits I“
.yad tsrif ruoy s’tI“
”,su fo eerht eht tsuj s’ti nehw klat reven uoY“
.esnopser ni dekrims eH ”?modnoc a dna
”.em edisni syot ym fo erutcip eht nees ev’uoY“
.degnip enohp ym sa dias I
dna loohcs hgih ni did I gnihtemos s’tI“ .denworf I
,gnituohs em ta devaw rosiv dna norpa na ni knuks a em dniheB
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
”?dda I od tahW“ ”.dnuora sgniht
!ti did uoy tub ,ton esruoc fO“
”.ton er’ew thgilyad daorb nI“ .deilper I
”.tnaw I tahw wonk uoy kniht I“
”,uoy fo duorp os m’I“
.em edisni saw eh
”,yddad ,haeY“ ”?eituc ,ydaer uoY“
,ekorb retaw eht fo ecafrus eht ylnedduS
”.liat rellams a htiw enoemos no ekil kool ll’ti tahw wonk dna
sfeirb ym devomer I ,ylkciuQ
,etatsorp ym tsniaga gnidnuop ehT
,thgirlA .eurt s’tahT“
.rekcup ym otni yaw sih desae eh sa
htaerb prahs a koot I ”.kcuf ,yddaD“
”,tol a ekat nac yllaer uoy ,haoW“
ti ot pu tnew I gnitniap eht derimda I sA .egami yremmus
?odeeps a ni em ees ot sremotsuc tsrif eht eb ot evah yeht did yhW
”.ees ot dlrow eht rof ereht tuo era ylleb dna shgiht gib ym ,lleW“
”.siht ekil sgniht od ot em ecnivnoc uoy woh wonk t’nod yllaer I“
os gnittes s’nus eht sseug I dna ,eniF“
.ti pota repparw eht tup I dna ,kcod eht ot em dediug ffilC
)moc tod rettiwT morf
ym deporg eh sa ylleb dna scep sih degassam I
”.revo refsnart dluoc slliks ruoy tuB“ .dias I
,ybraen enoyna fo em detrela eson ym fi kcod eht rednu dekcud ev’dluoc I
”.syad elpuoc a rof rehto hcae nwonk ylno ev’eW“
,noisserpmi doog a ekam ot tnaw tsuj I ,sseug I“
,reiruoc a tsuj ton er’uoY
.yawllah eht morf dias retto eht
”.uoy knahT“ .dias nosliW .srM
gnidnirg em dniheb tog dna em fo tnorf ni potpal eht dehsup eh sa dias I
,pohs eihtooms a ta krow ot retaw eht ssorca mih yrref em gnivah tpek lliB remmus tsaL
esolc em dellup ffilC sa ekal eht detanimulli noom lluf lavetsea ehT  .nus gnittes eht gnitaicerppa
.retaw eht otni evod dna strohs ym ffo koot I
”?pleh ot gniog siht s’woH“
.weksa eb ot desoppus saw emarf sti taht detseggus nihtiw gnitniap eht taht dezilaer I ti xif ot pu doots I sa dna detlit ylthgils saw sgnitniap eht fo enO
,rehtaew ecin eht derimda seye ym sa ecnelis ni tas tsuj ew edir eht hguorht yaw flah tuobA
.odeeps ym ni eglub eht ot detniop neht dna ,dehgis I
”.yrellag lanosrep ym ni meht peek ll’I neht
,rehto hcae wenk owt uoy ekil dednuos tI“
”,eno tsrif eht no dekcuf ew dnA“
.sexof eht ot wap a dednetxe eH ”.lehciE ffilC m’I“
.RP fo rotcerid eht ,naoJ m’I“
.kcuF ,hA“ .erised ym
”.rolias eht tcartsid t’nod ,teirraH“  .ezorf I ”.hu ,hO“
,yakO“ .smra sih dessorc neht nosliW .rM ”.egairram retfa ot drawrof kool ot evah syob uoy lla si sihT“
”!emit emos neeb sah ti ,hO“
”.enif eb dluohs tI“
potpal sih tuo thguorb eH
,saw yad sih woh mih deksa I
”,tniat yM“ ”?emit elohw siht
”?ffo trihs ruoy htiw siht gniod htiw elbatrofmoc eb uoy dluoW“
,nuf retawrednu emos dah owt eht neht dna
,su dnuora dlrow eht ot dekan yllacisab erew ew dna
knahT  .stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
a gnidloh no boj dooG“
.ylkciuq dias I ”,duol tsuj s’tI“
.neht dna won ti tuoba deklat sdneirf thgiarts ym dna ,retaw raen devil I ecnis ti tuoba denrael I tub
.keehc ym dessik dna dias eh
”.emuser ruoy ot gnidda dna pu gnignahc peek ot evah uoy os gnignahc yltnatsnoc er’yeht dna
.gnitegdif pu dne t’nod uoy os ereht drib elttil a s’ereht dneterp dna
”.elbarenluv gnieb osla elihw noitasrevnoc a dloh nac uoy taht ees ot tnaw osla I tub
yrots s’yadoT dna
,naicisum a si ohw ,gnoS lA yb
”,OEC putrats a era fo dnik uoy sseug I os
egnaro ysor a morf denrut yks eht sa retsaf neve gnittes saw nus eht nooS
.mih rof evitanretla repaehc a saw siht os rac a evah t’ndid eH
.detartsnomed dna dias eh
”,eseht dengised I nosaer rehtona saw sihT“
,ot tnaw uoy ,tiaW“
.retaw eht ot em dediug eh sa
”.tpecca yletinifed I“
”?yttar si liat ym gniyas uoy erA“
,redluohs ym ni hteet eht
.stnalp dettop dna sgnitniap llams ynam ni detaroced saw moor gnitiaw elttil ehT
”?naem uoy od tahW“
.larutan kool ot em detnaw dna noitcerid em evag eH
”.paC ,uoy no tcefrep skool tahT“
”.meht ekil yllaer ot mees uoY“
”.gniklat tpek eh dna
noitisop a detaerc ev’ew
.nwod dehcaer neht dna
,lufwa erew snoitidnoc eht em dlot eh dna
,9 raoR ,8 gnaF
”.ereh ekiL“ ”.uoy knahT“
otni em teg uoy woh dnatsrednu t’nod llits I“
.ekal eht no gnisirprus gnihtemos ta gnirats saw I ekil mees ot daeh ym tsuj nrut em dah eH
.trA fo muesuM notrevE eht ot emocleW“
.txen yas ot tahw wonk t’ndid I ”...naem I“
s’tI“  ”.taob eht fo tolip eht eb dluow I dna
”.sweivretni dna gnikrowten htiw uoy pleh ll’ti tub
”,tnereffid s’taht tuB“ ”.em ot klat uoY“
.srae ym fo spit eht ot esir
detaluspacne taht
rehtegot sniorg ruo debbur ffilC ’.elohtrop‘
”,taht ta doog htob er’ew wonk I dna
ylleb ym htiw won tub
,kcab s’etoyoc nedlog a ta aremac a gnitniop
.evitcarttanu yletelpmoc t’nsaw I em dewohs ffilC tub
,weivretni boj a ni yaw taht leef elpoep tsoM“ .deksa I
ebul citauqa taht sI“
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.loop eht fo egde eht no ti tes dna esac foorpretaw sti ni
”,oga syad wef a mih was tsuj ew ,teirraH“ .dias nosliW .srM
,ediug ruot a eb ot deilppa osla uoy ecnis tub
”,gniklat eht lla od uoy esuaceb s’tahT“ .dias ehs
.dellac eciov a ”?notliM“
,raewrednu citauqa eht otni sgel ym dedaerht dna elzzum ym ni meht tup neht I
,rof erew sodeeps ruoy thguoht I
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
pit ym morf etaname erp tlef I nooS
woleb wodniw eht ni noonretfa nmutua yniar eht ta
.sweivretni htiw uoy pleh ot gniog si sihT
.htaehs dna cas ym guh hcuop eht gnileef dna pu meht gniggut
I dnA“ .ecniw a dna
”.retnec gnilesnuoc reerac s’loohcs ym ni retsop a no senilediug eht dewollof
.koohs gel ym sa stsermra eht gnola sregnif ym gnippat
.smra reh dessorc ehS
”.flesruoy tuoba tsenoh eb ot tnaw uoy dna
:gnidulcni seigolohtna nezod a ni dehsilbup neeb sah lA
gninetsil rof uoy
”!kcarc ym ees nac uoY
”,gniht doog a ton s’taht gnisseug m’I“
.tfahs kciht sih nwod modnoc eht dellor I dna ,kcab nikserof sih llup em tel neht eH
,em denoops retto gib ehT
.ekatsim a saw rewsna taht dezilaer I
.trihs ym ffo koot dna dehgis I
”.os kniht t’nod I ,oN“
.riap esiouqrut dna emil rehtona em dednah dna dias eh
.erots erawdrah eht ot edir a dedeen ydkrahpgnoV .rM ekil dekool tI
uoy ot siht reffo ot ekil d’ew ,oS
,sserP xoF deruomrA yb
.denihw I dna redluohs ym otni tib eH
”?ekal eht ni kcuf annaw t’nod uoY“ ”?retaw eht ni …hu
erac t’ndid I taht saw
.kcod eht rednu miws nac uoy dna ,dnuora s’eno oN“
,ti ta er’ew elihW“
.no sfeirb emos tog
.sgninepo boj tnereffid rof dehcraes ew esruoc hsarc rettel revoc dna emuser eht retfA
”.emit eht lla sodeeps gniraew osla er’uoy sseug I“
.kcoj odeeps esiouqrut a gniraew rehpargotohp eht ta redluohs sih revo dekool ohw
.ylteews dias ehs
.yrarbil eht ta noitisop lacirelc level-yrtne na s’erehT“
.kcod eht otno pu su llup ot deganam ffilC neht dna
erom ni detoor yltsom si egdelwonk ym tub
.odeeps a ni retto revir egral eht gnirimda gnitniap eht ot ezag ym denruter I ”.doog sdnuoS“
.dias retto eht ”,noitasrevnoc
erofeb tem ev’ew kniht I“
”,niaga mih ees ot doog s’ti taht leef ylurt I tuB“
,krow reetnulov ,krow ,loohcs
.dnuora em denrut eH
nirg a htiw dias I
.klat ot detnaw I taht desirprus eh em dlot eh dna
”,notliM ,snoissap ruoy tuoba gniklat uoy raeh ot ecin os
,sklof citauqa rof yltsom saw dna ,retawrednu esu dluoc uoy ebul laiceps siht saw tI
.em edisni sregnif eerht devohs dna kcoc sih otno ebul eht deilppa eH
.taocniar gib a raew ot evah ton ot ecin saw ti woh tuoba gnikniht tpek I dna
.ni dils dna loop eht fo egde eht no potpal sih decalp eH
.dnuora meht yrref dna
,hcamots ym kcurts taht ssenisaeuq fo gnap a saw erehT
.tonk ym dniheb regnif gnir dna bmuht sih delcricne neht eH
.pu siht peek ot elba eb ot uoy tnaw I ,woN
,seitneves eht ni soaL evael ot gniyrt rof dellik neeb ev’dluoc eh em dlot eH
.aciremA ot tog eh nehw ylimaf yppah a detrats dna efil sih deksir eh tub
cirbaf eht hguorht shtped ykrum eht otni ecnesse ym dellips I sa
pihs uoy taht dna reiruoc a er’uoy taht etirw tsuj t’ndluohs uoY“
”.yawa sgnignoleb ruoy tup nac uoy os ksed ruoy ot teg s’tel tsrif tub
.ecin eb dluoc tahT“
.htaehs ym fo tuo tonk ym dellup dna odeeps ym fo tnorf eht otni sregnif sih deppid neht eH
eenk eno no doots eH
.em no odeeps a dna partskcoj a neewteb ssorc a ekil tlef tI
”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“
.ekal eht dnuora derettacs stod dna selgnatcer wolley wef a llits erew ereht tub ,ffo sthgil rieht dah sesuoh eht fo tsoM
?melborp eht s’tahW“ ”,tiaW“ .dias eh
,mmH“  .tnes dah I stnemhcatta eht denepo dna liame sih pu denepo eH
.loop moor gnivil eht ni gnidaw dias I
”.did I sseug I
stnemgarf ralimissid etinifni otni derettahs saw em edisni gnihtyreve
,gniyas saw I sA“ .detcejretni I
?siht tuoba erus uoy erA“
llehs sih fo tuo emoc notliM spleh
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.htaenrednu ecaps elttil a detaerc dna
”.ffo yadkeew deludehcs a evah ohw sediug eht rof ni llif ll’uoy erehw uoy rof
ti gniraew uoy ees ot ekil d’I tub
”.taerg taht ton s’ti wonk I“
.eno otni snoitisop htob enibmoc ot yaw a dnuof yltnecer ylno ew dna ,snaol tneduts ruoy ot eud emit-lluf krow ot erised a desserpxe uoY“ .deksa I
riahc citsalp dlo eht ni tas I # .was enoyna fi
.neercs eht ta detniop eH
.suoicsnoc-fles os tlef I
taeh eht tlef I dna
.odeeps ym fo kcab eht otni hctorc sih
.seitud boj tnerruc ruoy fo erom tuoba klaT“ .deksa I
ecno ta lla neht
”,tol a leehw gnireets eht gnippat uoy was I
.gnieerf elttil a tlef ti hguone ylddo dna
.selzzum s’rehtona eno ni decnad seugnot ruo sa esolc em dleh eh retaw eht ni dedaw ew sA
,meht ekil t’nod uoy fI
”.edir taob eht gnirud em ot gnihtyna yas neve t’ndid uoY
ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw ”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“ .ruoT dlroW
.potpal eht desolc ffilC dna denway I elihw a retfA
yzzit a otni em werht tonk ym dniheb esiv eht dna
.xaler ot em dlot taht em edisni gnihtemos saw ereht tub ,toh tlef ecaf yM
,gniugolatac dna
”,sekatsim ekam ot dewolla naht erom er’uoY
”.seot ruoy no kniht ot elba eb ot deen uoy dna ,snoitseuq uoy ksa ot gniog er’yehT
.em edisni gniworg
# ”.no kcab enigne eht gninrut m’I dna ,staes eht ot txen era srevreserp efil eht os
”,eno ysae na t’nsaw yadot hguoht ,sknahT“
yrtne atad fo stsisnoc yltsom elor ruoy tnatsissa eciffo na sA
”.srettel revoc dna emuser ruoy tuo kcehc s’teL“
,mih egadnab depleh ohw
.uoy rof kcirt a tog ev’I neht
.ot evah t’nod uoy neht siht htiw elbatrofmoc ton er’uoy fI“ ”.sseug I ,yakO“
,xulf ni lla era elpoep dna ,sdnert ,tekram eht
,haeY“  .delkcuhc eh
,gnitniap eht ni etoyoc eht sa tnemrag emas eht erow I sikahk ym htaenrednU
.kniw a htiw dias eh
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.ranegaT yb ”.S.C.C“ ,levon eht rof rotide na saw ooragnak der ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.gniniart dna slliks ruoy tuoba klat uoy erehw noitces a dna
”,taob ym no xes gnivah ton er’eW“
sliat gib htiw seiceps rehto dna ,sooragnak ,sretto
”.retaw eht otni ylisae taht ees nac elpoep ekil ton s’tI
elohd redlo eht pu dekcip I nehW
retto eht fo senomorehp dna ksum ytaews eht saw llems dluoc I gniht ylno eht tub
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.rood eht ot daeh ym gninrut dias I ”!seY“
rehtegot dnas eht ni tas ew sa ogidni fo seuh peed ot
.dias I ”,haey ,hU“
”.ti od nac uoy wonk I
”.yadot su htiw regnessap rehtona evah ew taht ees I“
”.seirarbil ekil od I
.kcod llams eht rednu dekcud I dna ,odeeps eht em dednah retto gib eht decafruser I sA
,dnabtsiaw eht evoba liat
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ekal eht otni deklaw ew sa dias I ”,eurt s’tahT“
rof yltsom si ngised siht oS“
”,raed ,s’lehciE eht rebmemer I“
”.ni uoy ees ot ekil d’I wen gnihtemos tog ev’I“
”.ylkciuq os sodeeps fo tuo dna
.raey siht gniht emas eht eb ot gniog saw ti ekil dekool ti dna
.gninaom dna gnilworg nageb eh sa citarre emaceb stsurht siH
;snoitces ruof etaerc ot uoy rof si tseggus I gniht enO
”.pu gnissem ton elihw
.dnuora dekool dna kcod eht no smra ym tup I sa dias I
”.metsys gnirebmun kcod elohw eht htiw depleh uoy taht tcaf eht dda ot deen osla uoY
,segakcap eldnah uoy pleh I sa gnol sa enif s’ti dias ssob ruoY“
”?edoc sserd a evah uoy oD“
”.ti ekil thgim uoy kniht I tub
.regnessap txen eht htiw noitasrevnoc a evah ot uoy tnaw I“
”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“
”!esruoc fO“ .deksa I
raewrednu ruoy ees yllaer ylno nac yeht sulP
uoy erA .trap drah eht ot teg s’tel
”,yadretsey pu tup ot detnaw uoy taht tra lanoitaripsni eht deviecer eW“
.ereht tuo flesmih tup nac eh taht os sehtolc dna