.trihsrednu ym devomer dna htaerb a koot I
”…fi gnirednow saw I dna
”?ssik a evah I naC“
hcum os mih derehtob ti fI
.kcoc ym dnuora elzzum sih tlef ylneddus I
,elttil a ti gnivom deirt I os dekoorc saw ti dna ,su ot txen llaw eht no gnuh llorcs A
.sdnilb eht gnisolc nageb eh dna ,ni deppets eW
”?etad a eb ot siht tnaw t’nod uoY“  ”.heh ,s’ti ,I .naem I“
.em nihtiw retlik-ffo tnew gnihtyreve dna
”.uoy rof gniledom emos od em tel
,ppa edyR eht fo noisrev taob a od ot aedi rieht saw ti ,llew ,mH“
”?tuo evom stnerap ruoy did yhw
,hctorc sih revo odeeps sih tup dna dnuora denrut eh tub
.boj ym rof ti deen I tuB“
sih depsarg I dna
thguoht I .yrotsih tra ni ronim a htiw rojam scissalc a m’I“
.mih ta pu delims dna dias I ”,thgirlA“
.ecaf ym ot hsur taeh tlef I sa dias retiaw eht
”,taht teg em tel ,ereH“
.nwod kcab evod dna
.elzzum s’retto gib eht otni ecnesse ym gnitrups
.loop eht fo egde eht no meht tup I enodnu erew yeht ecno dna ,ylteiuq dekrow eW
,ylecin cas ym ffo dewohs ti
.gnidnuop traeh ym gnileef ,detseggus I
.gel ym tsniaga ssendrah sih gnibbur nageb dna denaom eh
,ffo srefaol ym koot I
”.doog naht retteb m’I ,on ,doog m’I“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”?kcod eht ta pu teem ew llahS !doog sdnuoS“
.os erom neve saw elzzum sih tub
,lleW“ .ylkciuq dias eh
em dessik dna decafruser eH
,yldab os desaeler eb ot detnaw stnap ym tsniaga erusserp eht tub
t’ndid I ,yrros m’I ,hO“
”.ma I ,haeY“ ”,gib os er’uoY“
,osrot sih ssorca dirg a ni snep niatnuof eseht lla dah trihs-t siH
”?ereh dnuora secalp doog yna fo wonk uoy oD“ .yltfos dias eh
,oot uoy ekil yllaer I .tluda na m’I
.tnemetats a flah dna noitseuq a flah saw tI ”.knim retaw
.leehw eht evoba draobhsad eht otni demmals elzzum ym dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,taht od uoy kniht t’nod I“
”,lufituaeb er’uoy kniht I“
.erutinruf eht ta gninworf dias I
’sey‘ ,maercs ot detnaw taht em fo trap a saw erehT
”?tsaf ot gniog I mA“
.niaga flesym gniporg nageb I sa dias I
kcoc ym fo noitasnes eht ta dehctiwt dna
ti elbat eht no smraerof ym tup dna nwod tas I nehW
,nekahs saw eroc ym tnemom taht tA .delggig eh
.eerht-ytnewt m’I .taht ton s’tI“
ria eht otni deirc I
.daeh sih dekcoc dna deksa eh
.dias retto eht ”,detpoda m’I“
,stnemhsilpmocca ym ot deit ecnedifnoc-
”.ti teg dna emoc neht
wap eno htiw sllab ym dleh eH
.em ta ylthgirb gnilims dias eh
”.paC ,gib ytnelp er’uoY“
”?gnihtyna yas eh t’ndid yhw neht
.su derongi meht fo tsom tub
”,taob ruoy naht tnatropmi erom yaw si htlaeh ruoY“
,erehwon fo tuo em htiw pu ekorb eh tub
.em ta gnilims dias eh
,slias ruoy tsujda ot deen tsuj uoy os
”.setunim wef a tsuj em evig ,hu ,dna ,eruS“
.liat yvaeh ,egral sih detfil eh sa skeehc evissam sih ffo gniwohs
”.sraef ym fo eno s’tahT“
,krow ot kcab tog I dna
”.deneppah yllaer t’nsah taht tub
.detrulb I ”,sknaht ,heH“
.etnaseP ekaL fo nwot llams eht hguorht skcolb wef a deklaw eW
niaga ylpeed em dessik eH
.sepytoerets wollof ot deen uoy naem t’nseod taht tub
”,sey snaem tI“ ”…naem taht seoD“
”?thgir ,retawrednu ees nac sretto wonk uoY“
.yawa skcolb wef a tsuj saw cinilc ni-klaw eht lufetarg saw dna pu doots I
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.ylgnirussaer dias eh
.reiruoc a m’I yhw ksa yeht dna
,sselmia saw I egelloc retfA“
,cas ytfeh sih delaever dna ecnats sih denediw neht eH
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”?erofeb dneirfyob a dah uoy evaH“
.hcum os kcab em dleh tahw s’ti kniht I dna
.ksum dna tlas ekil dellems ti dna odeeps eht deson I ”.eituc
”.tcejbus eht egnahc ot yrt tsuj I
.tuo wap sih htiw taob eht no gnileenk retto gib eht ta pu dekool I
,levon eht rof rotide na saw ooragnak der ehT
.eb ot ecalp taerg a ton s’ti wonk I dna
,etnaseP ekaL dnuora strohs ro sknurt miws ni syug was yllamron I sremmus eht gniruD
.em ta detniop yeht sa
,noitavirped-fles otni er’uoy fi ,lleW“
”?yduts uoy did tahW“
.ti no rebmun a htiw drac ssenisub a em evag eH
loop a ta er’ew ecniS“
,gnikcus eht od tsuj I yllausU“
,moorhtab eht deretne dna ,loop eht dnuora deklaw I
,sniol ym otni gnivom wolf doolb ot del hcihw
.egakcap nwo ym gniporg retaw eht ni deddon I
.taht ni gninnuts os kool uoY“
.shtped mraw eht otni deknils dna
.slessev htob egamad dna taob tsiruot eht otni hsarc yllaitnetop dna
.elttil a denruhc hcamots yM
,remmus gnirud ecnetsixe ym fo enab eht ,stsiruoT
sniatnuom eht fo saw rehto eht elihw ,seert mlap htiw hcaeb a fo saw eno
.wap ym ni pmuj dna krej ti tlef I sa mraw dna elbidercni saw htgnel sih fo ssenkciht ehT
”.setoyoc etuc ekil I .thgirla s’tI“
.mih otni em dehsup dna skeehc ym fo hcae debbarg eH
,flesym decarb I tub
”?retaw eht ot noitnetta gniyap t’nerew uoy yhw siht saW“
saw tI“ .yltfos dias ffilC
”.no krow ot deen I gnihtemos s’ti ebyam os
”.suoregnad siht eb dluow reiruoc a gnieb ezilaer t’ndid I
,wodniw sih no sniatruc owt dah eH
”.yrros os m’I .yrros m’I“
,tnet a gnihctip saw I ecnis ffo elttil a mees did ti thguohT
,naicisum a si ohw ,gnoS lA yb
.em evoba morf erusaelp ni gnitnap mih raeh ot dna erp sih etsat ot gnizama saw tI
,tnaruatser eht ta devirra ew nooS
.ylmraw delims eh
.reggib erew retaw eht gnidnuorrus seitic dna snwot rehto eht tub
seigolohtna nezod a ni dehsilbup neeb sah lA .ranegaT yb ”.S.C.C“
,ehtaerb kcoc ym tel ot taerg tlef ti tub ,dessarrabme tib a llits saw I ”,taht wenk I“
”.eerged a tog ev’uoY“ .yltneg dias eh
,nairategev a m’I .yrros m’I ,hO“
spil ruo neewteb dexim secnesse ruo sa
.tik dia tsrif llams a kcab thguorb eh sa gniffup dna gniffuh kcab nar retto revir ehT  .ecin saw taht os ,ecnarusni taob dah I tsael tA
.esolc pu em derimda dna moor eht ssorca maws neht ffilC
,detiaw ,ni dekcehc I
,em ot htolc eht dednah eH
.riahc eht ni kcab denael neht dna
”.pleh nac I .dia tsrif wonk I“
”.dnaherofeb rewohs t’ndid I taht dnim t’nod uoy epoh I“
,mM“ .meht dekrow yltneg I sa psarg ym ni ecaps hcum os pu koot sllab siH
.reywal a dedeen I fi deksa dna
,seeyolpme RH htiw lenap weivretni eht no ni tis d’I dna
.sllab dna kcoc ym depsarg dna ,flesmih degrembus eH ”.tseggib
.gnihtyreve rof retto eht deknaht osla I
”.etsat a ti evig dna pu nepO“
.ylleb ybbuhc sih gniknalf smra delcsum ,kciht
.seye ym ni niap eht etaba depleh retto revir eht drawot gnikool os
em ta kcab dekool retto gib ehT
gnilley emos draeh I sa ksa eciov enotirab ,peed a draeh I ”?yako uoy erA“
,tfel eht ot leehw eht denrut ylkciuq dna kcab elttorht eht deknay I .noisiced ysae na saw tI
.kcab saw retiaw eht gnimit tcefrep s’esrevinu eht htiw esruoc fO
”?haeY“ .tser eht esarhp
.tseggib eht ton m’I wonk I“
”,oga emit gnol a ti dengised I“
”,enoyna tespu t’ndid I epoh yllaer I
1 traP ,gnoS lA yb
,tsewhtroN cificaP eht fo ytisrevinU eht ot og ,sedarg doog teG
woh wonk t’ndid I
”,taert a rof ni er’uoy sseug I neht
”.kcod eht otno tog I
”.em ot kcab teg reven yeht ro
,uoy no gnikcip pots ll’I“
annaw uoY“ .sesop tnereffid ni em rof specib sih dexelf eh sa odeeps sih dexif dna retaw eht fo tuo debmilc ffilC
.noissucnoc a evah t’nod uoy erus ekam
”,emoclew er’uoY“ ”!uoy knaht ,hO
”.neht rewols tib a og
.mih htiw supmac raen evil ot ti gnidneps fo daetsni snaol ym rof yap ot raey roines ym morf yenom tnarg taht desu ev’dluoc I tub ,sseug I“
:dliuG eht morf selaT dna ,9 raoR
”.ARI htoR ym ot seog yenom artxe taht woN
,egaw muminim revo rallod a tuoba ekam I won tuB
ot yrt ohw syug ’revelc‘ eht era ereht nehT
”.boj elbidercni na did uoY
.enigne eht fo raor eht revo mih raeh ot hguot saw ti tub
loop eht fo egde eht no tas dna flesmih derewol ffilC
.daeh sih dekcoc dna deksa eh
.tnemom taht ta drah kcor emaceb I dna
,emit emas eht ta ffuts yag eht dna
,mih ot revo delddap I
,dias dna mih deknaht I
,eerged ym htiw krow eciffo fo tros emos mrofrep ro tnatsissa nimda na emoceb tsuj dluoc I
taht tsuj s’ti dna
,yaw hcae setunim evif-ytrof ekil koot tI .enif saw ti dna
”?ti teg uoy did erehW
.eromyna stnemyap egagtrom ekam t’ndluoc dad ym fi od d’I tahw wonk neve t’nod I“
.sselesu gnileef fo derit m’I
”.oga sraey elpuoc a ta saw I thgiew emas eht ta yltcaxe ton m’I tub
dna erac tnegru ot uoy teg s’tel tsrif tuB“
.daeh sih dniheb swap sih tup eh dna ,sgel ym neewteb tnew liat sih sa snoitartsinim ym deunitnoc neht I
.ylleb ym tsniaga gniniarts saw nottub htfif eht esruoc fo dna ,trihs pu-nottub deveels trohs a otni degnahc I ”.noos
.ni teef ym deppid dna
.sgniht luftruh yas tsuj yeht semitemos dna ,seugnot prahs htiw rehtona eno tramstuo
.yldnik dias eh ”!esruoc fO“
fles ym dah yletinifed I neht kcaB
.em erofeb sretaw gniremmihs eht dennacs I sa delims dna drawrof elttorht eht degdun yltneg I  2 fo
.elzzum ym ni ti decalp eh dna
neerg emil thgirb a saw flah eno dna
.esnopser ni naorg dluoc I lla saw ”,hgU“
”,deeccus ot uoy tnaw I
.retawrednu gnieb ti etipsed
.drawrof elttil a daeh ruoy pit dna
,mraw saw flesti retaw ehT
,teews ylbidercni er’uoy kniht I ,haeY“
.mrif gnisitrevda na ni krow ot elba saw I
,elbuort siht lla hguorht uoy gnittup rof riap a uoy teg ll’I
.enohp ym ni rebmun sih tup I ’senoJ eht ot egakcap eht tog I retfa dna
.spord wef a trups kcoc nwo ym tlef dna odeeps eht ni erp ytlas eht detsat I
”?ffuts weivretni htiw em pleh osla uoy naC“
”?erofeb esuoh citauqa na ni neeb reve uoY“
raewmiws maertsniam htob gnitaerc nageb I neht dna
.kcod eht fo egde eht ot nwod klaw retto revir egral a deciton I wob eht ot kcab gninruT
,em rof ti dexelf eh ylevixelfer dna
”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“
.gninialpmoc ym lla htiw yppahnu mih gnikam saw I em dlot dna
,dah reve dah I tseb eht fo emos edam yeht ecnis ,su rof irani artxe deredro I
.kcab flesym dloh t’ndluoc I wenk I tub
”.hsifles gnieb saw eh dettimda neve xe ym dna
.unem eht hguorht gnikool llits
,8 gnaF :gnidulcni
.egakcap evissam sih deppuc dna nwod yaw ym tlef I
”.ekil d’uoy fi taht em llac nac uoY
.tnemom taht ta ffo detlem ev’dluoc ecaf ym ekil tlef tI
.redluohs ym no wap a gnittup dias eh
.ti fo tuo gniwolf kni htiw deppans saw elddim eht raen eno tub
.evila llits ylbaborp saw I os
.em hsalps ot gniog saw eh thguoht I ecnis
”,eerf mih tel no emoC“
,snalg evitisnes sih dnuora eugnot ym gnilriwS
,serohc eht fo tsom did
.mih raeh t’ndid srebmem ffats eht gnipoh em dnuora dekool yletaidemmi I dna ,deksa eh
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT       .erusaelp fo
.dlrow eht ni pu evom ot od ot tahw wonk t’nod I dna
.ylesnemmi pu gnimraw ecaf ym tlef I dna ,dias eh
,kool egnarts a mih evag elpoep wef a dna
sih fo hcae no krow wap hcae gnittel
”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“   yojne esaelP
,thgir eht ot leehw gnireets ym gninrut ,etar efas a ta gnitareleced fo gniht reporp eht od dluoc I
ylirgna gnitalucitseg stnerap rieht htiw em fo tnorf ni thgir
,sselemoh neeb ev’dluow ylbaborp eh em tuohtiw taht dias eH
”?uoy t’nac ,laog taht eveihca llits nac uoY“
.ylleb gib dna smra gnorts sih gnirimda mih ta pu dekool I sa flesym dnuora smra ym depparw I dna ,osrot erab sih ffo gniwohs desserdnu ffilC
”.semit wef a ,haeY“
elihw tnet a gnihctip kniht I“
# ”.taht rof pu m’I ,eruS“ ”?haey ,hU“
”?tuo em gnipleh rof rennid uoy teg dluoc I fI“
”.kool uoy woh ekil I“
.selzzum s’rehto hcae otni denaom ew sa enim tsniaga gnippal eugnot sih tlef I
,em rof deirrow dna dekcohs erew yehT
”.em ediug pleh ot ereht saw eno on ekil tlef I dna
.sredro ruo koot dna retaw su thguorb ooragnak ehT
.ria eht ni pu kcoc sih htiw gnitaolf retaw eht otni deppils eh sa dnoces a rof no dloh ot em deksa dna kcab denael neht eH
,daeh sih dniheb swap sih tup
ot pu neeb ev’I tahw ksa sdneirf dlo nehW
.tolgylop dna ,retirw
.su erofeb deyalpsid tnemertuocca elbide dna
.edisrednu eht rof doog t’nsaw ylbaborp tahT
,maerc eci aet neerg ahctam
,iaznez deredro retto eht dna
”.etad tsrif a gnirud sexe tuoba gniklat eb t’ndluohs I wonk I .yrros m’I“
.ecin yllaer s’ti ,haeY“
.odeeps sih ot gnirutseg dias eh
,odeeps a tsuj gniraew nwot hguorht deklaw eh woh wonk t’nod I
,syad esoht tsinoitcefrep a hcus saw I
.kcod eht ta nwod gnirats deddon I
,thgirpu tis ot uoy tnaw tsuj I ,thgirlA“
I tub ,niap ni saw I
,kcod eht morf em ta devaw eH
.sesor eht llems ot emit ekat syawla dluow I
.eson ym tsniaga ti dloh ot em dlot dna segadnab nottoc emos tuo dellup eH
”.ni levart dluohs I noitcerid hcihw erus ton llits m’I tub
.rorrim eht ni etoyoc eht ta dekool dna ni ti tog I yllautnevE
.odeeps yvan dna esiouqrut a saw erow eh lla taht tcaf eht saw siht tuoba trap tseb ehT
”.desu os leef tsuj I ,haeY“
,kciht ylevisserpmi saw kcoc siH
”’,deticxe‘ uoy tog s’regnad ekil skool tI“
.enim ni ti koot I dna ,wap a tuo dleh ffilC
”.yaw taht leef yletinifed I“
.lehciE ffilC m’I“
.thgir eht ot ylthgils gninael ot kcab gniog tpek ti tub
,meht ta deppal I sa sllab sih neewteb thgir tnew eson ym dna ,elzzum ym fo tuo odeeps eht koot I
,oga sraey ynam raewmiws gningised detrats I“
,detcurtsni saw I sa did I
.gnihton gniod saw ti ekil tlef ti taht tsaf os gnitaeb saw ti ebyam ro
hcus dah dna llat saw eH
”?eituc ,gniod uoy era woH“
”,sngised ym no flesym niatsus ot elba saw I nehw oga sraey wef a litnu t’nsaw ti dna
,tfel dah taob rehto eht dezilaer I taht retal litnu t’nsaw tI
.daehkcoc ykael ,thgirb sih dnuora spil ym depparw dna kcab nikserof sih dellup I ”.eituc
.pihs ym gnigamad ylno elihw kcod eht otni gnihsarc dna ,tfel eht ot gninrut
,emosdnah yllaer er’uoy dna
”.revlos melborp a er’uoy swohs tahT
’ibasaW ibaS-ibaW‘
.thgir s’eh sseug I tub
,uoy morf nwod sesuoh wef
,wap ym rof dehcaer eh dekcod taob eht tog eh retfA  ’.eit‘
.htaerb rehtona koot dna
elbatrofmocnu leef ot uoy tnaw t’nod I
.reveostahw teews gnieb ton ti etipsed
.em ot nevig saw taht esuoh a ni evil osla I tub ,ssob nwo ym m’I woN“
,elgna thgils a ta saw tI
.sunem ruo su dednah neht dna ,su detaes ooragnak egral A
.deretnec yllanif saw ti litnu ylthgils llorcs eht devom eH
,revelc dna yttiw eb dluohs I etoyoc a m’I esuaceb taht yas ohw elpoep era erehT
.os kniht I“ ”?klaw uoy naC
”.thgit tis tsuJ“ .ybraen esuoh llams a ta gnitniop dias eh ”,uoy rof segadnab emos teg em tel ,ereh thgir evil I“   .taob ym ni tned egral eht ta gninworf nwod tas I dna ,kcod eht fo sknalp nevenu eht otno em depleh eh neht dna
,yako s’ti fi wonk ot detnaw I“
”.deretsulf lla teg uoy hctaw ot nuf hcum os s’ti tub
.pu gnimraw skeehc dna srae
eno siht piks esaelp
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sngised gniwes dna senizagam noihsaf ekil dekool tahw morf segami ot detacided saw edis etisoppo eht no llaw ehT
ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw ”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“ .ruoT dlroW
”,ereh metsys gninaelc citamotua na tog ev’I .doog lla s’tI“
”,ekil skool noitcefrep tahw si siht ,oS“
.osrot dna niorg ym ni gnidliub erusserp eht leef dluoc I dna
?emuserp I ,esuoh s’lehciE eht otni devom uoy …er’uoy dna ,haeY“
,cep sih otno wap a tup I sa resolc em dellup eH
.doowladnas dna seirrehc ekil dellems hcihw
,dias eh ”,gniht eruS“
”?elbatrofmoc erom uoy ekam taht dluoW“ .deksa eh
,pu meht dellup I nehw dna ,sdap wap ym no yklis dna ecin tlef lairetam ehT
”?erom em pleh uoy dluow yhW“
”?egelloc ni yduts uoy did tahW“
em kcus ot tnaw uoy fI“
.ekil d’uoy fi moorhtab eht ni degnahc teg nac uoY“
,em fo tnorf ni eglub fo tol a saw erehT
.derettu tsuj I sdrow eht ta ezorf neht dna ,denaom I ”,yddad hO“
.em tsniaga erised sih fo gnileef eht ta pmuj kcoc nwo ym tlef I dna
.em ot meht dednah dna noitingi eht morf syek eht debbarg retto ehT
erew yeht tuB“ ”.nos rieht m’I
.mih gnikorts nageb dna kcoc kciht
,eurt s’taht sseug I“
.edis eht ot elttil a gnitniop saw ti dna
ti ecnis erutaef etilletas eht gnivah tsuj fo daetsni kcod hcae gnirebmun yb tuo depleh I dna
.dnuorgkcab eht ni gniyrc dna
.yawllah a otni del taht loop egral a delaever hcihw rood tnorf eht dekcolnu ffilC
.tnemom siht ni ekam dluoc I seciohc wef a dah I
teews a etaerc ot
”.emuser ruoy ta kool a ekat yletinifed nac I os
.kool nac uoY .thgirla s’tI“
.erp fo spord elpuoc a kael em edam hcihw ,odeeps sih gnilaever
”.thgir eht no rood tsrif eht s’tI
”?thgir ,niatpac taob ehT“
”?rewol og I naC“
”.ti gniledom rof uoy knahT“
,dias I tressed retfA
,taob ym ot kcab deklaw eW
,nus eht gnicaf saw I
meht devomer neht eH
.uoy morf noitatiseh emos eb thgim ereht
,sraey owt tsrif ym gnirud elttaeS ot emoh morf detummoc I
.htiw ylper dluoc I lla saw ”,uoy knahT“
”.nwod ti eit ll’I dna epor eht em eviG“ ”.yako m’I kniht I“
,arupmet ,sllor eht eta ylippah ew dna ,devirra doof ruO
.buhc a gnitteg ylwols mih deciton I sa em erofeb thgis eht ni knard I ”.meht dengised I
”.tuo mih pleh ot uoy fo elbon osla
.sleef ti doog woh wonk ot evresed uoy dna
”’?boj tnerruc ruoy ta evisserpmi kool uoy sekam taht enod uoy evah tahw‘ fo
.ti edih ot yrt ot erom nwod ralloc eht gut ot deirt I dna
”.gnihtemos s’taht sseug I os ,raey siht owt tog I“ .deksa eh
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
nwod taob rieht gniwols
.ylthgirb dias eh
”?nwolb gnitteg ekil ton uoy oD“
.eit ym didnu I sa dias I ”,thgirla s’ti ,oN“
,deksa I sesuap erom wef a retfA
”.ecnedifnoc tsuj s’ti gniyas yb roivaheb dab rieht esucxe dna tnagorra tca ohw elpoep eseht lla ekil ton er’uoY
thgie-ytriht m’I esuaceb taht yrrow tsuj I dna
.pal ym revo swap ym tup dna sgel ym dessorc yletaidemmi I
a tsuj m’I naem I
”,paC ,doog lla s’tI“ ”...ot naem
.stsiruot gnuoy elpuoc a pu ecils ylbaborp dna ,drawrof gnidaeh peek ,kcab elttorht eht knay dluoc I
,erofeb noitisop ruoy neeb ev’I“
.kcab ym fo llams eht debbur eh sa dias eh ”,yletinifed ,haeY“
.erohs eht ot esolc yllaer saw ti dna retaw eht ni gnibbob t’nsaw taob ym dezilaer I dna
,ekal otni gnipmuj skcub gnuoy elpuoc a dna
.retaw fo pis a koot dna dias eh
”.gnizama kool uoy erus m’I oS“ .yltneg dias eh
,deksa I yltnatiseH
”?tsrif si ti tahw ees dluoc I ebyam ,llew ,hu ,hO“
.scep sih ta gnikool tsuj ecin osla saw ti ,yldettimdA
.noos tuo daeh ll’I .doog sdnuoS“
,ssendrah sih tsniaga dehsurb gel ym sa
”?uoy ot detcartta t’nerew I fi esuoh ym otni emoc uoy tel I dluow yhW“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”?trihs ym ekil uoY“
ym tlef I dna ,em ta devaw eH
,ksa ot drawrof oot ton s’ti epoh I“
.ecaf toh a htiw ylkeem dias I ”,yakO“
.naelurec looc a saw rehto eht elihw
”reiruoC yranoisiV eht fo noitcefreP“
”.meht ekil ll’uoy kniht I“
deredro I dehsinif ew nehW
.eson ym fo pit eht ta nottoc eht gnipeek daeh ym fo kcab eht ot dna elzzum ym dnuora ti gnittif
”,elbaroda ylemertxe er’uoy kniht I“
.dda ot gnihtemos yletinifed s’taht ,yeH“
,retaw raelc eht ot revo deklaw
,ereH“ .niaga deddon I
”.htiw uoy pleh nac I gnihtemos s’taht ebyaM“
”?yadot em tem tsuj uoy hguoht nevE“
.ylteiuq dias I ”?yllaeR“
retal raey a tuoba dna gnitekram ni sesruoc elpuoc a koot dna ,egelloC ytinummoC elttaeS tseW ot tnew neht I
moortser eht fo tuo gnippetS
rood eht ot deklaw neht I
.mih ta derats dna ezorf I ”?tahw-hW“
”?won krow rof od uoy od tahW
,gniht emas eht deman erew ekal dna nwot eht yhw derednow syawla I
,oN“ .deksa I ”?drawkwa
eerged s’rolehcab a evah I taht elpoep llet I nehw ti etah yllaer llits I tub
”.reverof ni etad a no neeb t’nevah osla I ,haey ,hU“
”.hcum oot nialpmoc I
.eit‘ yas mih ot denetsil I sa redrah gnitteg saw I kniht
”.reilrae morf etoyoc eht
.meht tuoba doog leef ot srehto morf noitadilav dedeen I dna
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.rehto eht naht regnol saw ti tub ,ekal a dna
,dnab citsale eht dehcterts dna ksam lacigrus lacinoc a depparwnu eH
”,taob ruoy ni rotom a tog ev’uoy ,lleW“
”?esuoh a gnitirehnI“
,oot lareneg ni syug yag tuoba taht yas yehT“
,strA eht fo egelloC iklA ta ngised ni derojam I“
.nwonk ev’I ohw elpoep eht fo tsom morf ecap fo egnahc ecin a s’ti
,egelloc ytinummoc ot og ot duorp oot saw em fo trap A
.eituc ,ezigolopa ot deen t’nod uoY“  ”.yrros os m’I“
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF no
.rood eht denepo dna
”?siht od ew sa no sehtolc ruoy peek ot referp uoy dluoW“
.foorpkcohs dna foorpretaw ti tpek esac ’laeS lairepmI‘ ehT
”?hsif htiw gnihtemos evah annog uoy erA“
teews er’uoy taht ekil I
”,em no emalb eht tup os pu ti thguorb I“
,tuons eht no em dessik eH
.elttil a ti koohs dna redluohs sih debbarg I
duht duol a draeh I
,notliM si siht ,hu ,yeH“
.mih ta pu delims dna ecnesse ytlas sih pu deppal I
,lanoitcnuf llits saw taob yM
.sretsop eivom dna sgnitniap htiw dellif llaw yrellag a dah eH
.llehs sih fo tuo emoc etoyoc eht spleh retto eht hcihw ni yaw yxes eht dna
sessergorp pihsnoitaler s’notliM dna ffilC woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
evom ot elba saw I fi deksa eH
.retaw eht evoba tcejbo eht htiw kcab maws eh sa wap sih ni dedlof gnihtemos dah neht eH
.hsad eht otno elkcaps doolb fo skceps wef a was dna dehguoc I
”.em rof no gnihtemos yrt dluoc uoy fi ees ot detnaw I
,snoitacilppa ynam os ni tup ev’I .erus ton m’I“
,deppots traeh yM
,enif saw I dlot ,kcab dellac saw
,dias eh sa dennirg dna
.notgnihsaW nretsew ni ynnus emaceb yllautca ti nehw
!paC ,emosewa saw tahT“
.gnileef eht ta depsag I dna ,kcoc ym dnuora elzzum sih tup eH
,drah gnikarb saw noitpo tsal ehT
,nosrep yppah yrev a t’nsaw eh ekil sdnuos tI“
”?eseht ekil uoy ti ekat I“
”,esaelp ,seY“ ”?I yaM“
”.eman ruoy tog reven I ,hu ,yrros m’I
.era yeht toh dna gnorts woh ffo wohs ot tnaw ohw ,smod erucesni ,hguot ,gib eht era erehT
”,pots nac I neht ,ti ekil t’nod uoy fI“
.evil ot ecalp a dah eh erus edam dna
.wal eht htiw elbuort ni teg reven dna
detcejer teg I rehtie tub
.tem spil ruo neht dna nihc ym gnitfil
”.em ot taht dias s’ohw nosrep tsrif eht ton er’uoY“
.seye ym fo srenroc eht ta pu gnillew sraet tlef I sa tib a rof desuap neht I
.decafruser eh sa deksa eh ”?gnorw s’tahW“
.elbat ylbbow a teg syawla I yhw wonk t’nod I“  .tib a dekcor
”.noitacol lautca rieht morf yawa sdray ynam er’yeht ekil kool sregnessap eht ekam dluow ti os sdaor no desucof eb ot demees
”.no gnihtyna tuohtiw em nees s’nosrep rehto eno ylno
noitcocnoc ytlas dna
.thgir gnihtyreve did I thguoht I ,ekiL
senil eht gnola gnihtemos saw netfo ksa d’ew taht noitseuq a yllausu ,eruS“
,boj emit lluf ym htiw eiregnil yag fo smrof sa spohs xes ot meht gnilles yltsom saw I dna
”.uoy knahT“ .trihs ym gninottubnu nageb eh dna
,boj ym tuoba em ot tcaer elpoep rehto woh no dneped t’ndluohs flesym tuoba leef I woh wonk I ekil s’tI“
”.htuom ruoy hguorht ehtaerb ylnO
”?kcid ruoy dekcus reven xe ruoy em gnillet uoy erA“
”,gniht eruS“ ”?em nioj ot eraC“
.ylkciuq deruoved ew hcihw fo htob
”.od dluow nosrep doog yna tahw s’tI“
.srefaol nworb tseb ym dna sikahk fo riap a no werht neht I
”.uoy teg ot tuo ton er’yeht erus m’I .no emoC“
.aet neerg toh dna ’sthgileD eiggeV‘ tog htob eW
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.kcen ym dnuora thgiarts tonk eht teg t’ndluoc I ecnis ,setunim wef a rof dekcinap dna ralloc eht rednu eit a depparw neht I
.deyaled eb dluow yreviled rieht taht dna ,deneppah tahw wonk meht tel dna ,ecnediser senoJ eht dellac I
.enif s’tI“ .yltneg dias eh
”…demuserp evah t’ndluohs I dna
”?kcuf dna ecalp ym ot kcab og annaw uoy naem uoY“ ”?sngised ruoy
s’teL”  .rehtona eno ta delims ew sa mih ta pu dekool dna ylteiuq dias I ”,uoy knahT“
rood kcab eht tuo deppets I
.yug rehtona rof em tfel fo tros eh
,dniw eht fo noitcerid eht egnahc t’nac uoy yas yeht wonk I dna
dias eh ”,esruoc fO“
”,ni m’I tbed eht lla htiw nwo ym no tnemtrapa na tner ot neve ro rac wen a ro
,deilper I ”,eruS“ .deksa eh
.ti laets dluow eno on os taob eht ni egakcap eht debbarg osla eH
,em tcartsid ot depleh ylno taht ydob ym fo snoiger ot gnipmup doolb dah I ,sselehtreveN
tsehc sih ot kcab reppu sih morf yaw sti tlef wap yM
.retaw eht rednu odeeps ym nwod dellup I dna ,dias eh
.kool gnirussaer a em evag ffilC dna elbat eht ta ylsuovren derats neht I
.dlrow siht ni pu evom nac I epoh yllaer I“
”?yako gniod uoy erA“
kool lacirtemmysa na ti gnivig rehto eht naht renniht saw meht fo edis enO
.eciov peed s’retto revir eht draeh I ”,olleH“
”.hcum os ezigolopa ot deen t’nod uoy ,paC“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.ylbbow era selbat eht lla ebyam ,haeY“
”,pleh rof meht deksa dna sniwt dah yltnecer ehs ecnis ,esuoh s’retsis ym otni devom yehT“
.ruf ym tsniaga taerg dekool dna ecin saw odeeps eht tub
”.tsom eht em gnipleh pu dedne tahw s’ti tub
,erehwyreve su evord I taht tcaf eht etipsed
.nirg a htiw dias eh
”,dnik os gnieb rof uoy knahT“
”.em htiw eb ot tnaw yllautca dluow spot taht os ynniks erew I hsiw I“
,ereht ni ecaf ruoy teG“
tuo kcehc I nac ,hu ,ew fi
”.uoy ekil yllaer I ,paC“ ”.yakO“
,tnemtraped ngised eht rof gnirih htiw pleh ot desu I“
.hcuop eht otni kcoc ym gnitteg ytluciffid dah I tub
,raey tsal noitaudarg erofeb tub ,egelloc ni sraey owt rof yug a detad I ,haeY“
.srehto ot evitcartta llits saw I fi ees ot suoiruc saw taht em fo trap rehtona saw ereht dna
,sserP xoF deruomrA yb sfeiraeB ro srexoF
”.gnilggurts yllaer m’I tub
,yawllah eht fo dne eht ta decafruser ,retaw eht hguorht detekcor eH
,em ot neppah taht ot ralimis gnihtemos dah ev’I dna
”,elbaroda os er’uoY“
,ksa ot yako s’ti fI“
,dnuora gnitaolf kcuts eb annog tsuj m’I
dias eh ”,nagev m’I“
!uoy etad ot tnaw I !od I“
”.taht od ot evah t’ndluohs uoy
.gniht emas eht deksa eh dna ,ssob ym dellac neht I
,etacorpicer ot tnaw I“ ”.on ,lleW“
.saw eh gib woh ees ot gnitnaw denihw I dna
. retaw eht otni kcab sgel sih gnippid
,htaerb peed a koot I sA
.kool denrecnoc a em evag tsuj ffilC tub ,dekcuhc I
.odeeps rehtona gnilaever ti denepo I dna
,regnol tsal ot detnaw I
”.drac ym s’ereh dna
,retaw eht sdrawot detniop eh sa nwod dna pu gnipmuj dna ,gnituohs saw eH
”?pleh ekil uoy dluoW“
.odeeps eht otni deppets I sa renob ym
.mih ta pu gnilims dias I ”,haeY“ ”?ydaer uoY“
”.reveostahw melborp on s’tI
.ylgnirussaer dias eh
.ssik eht ekorb ylneddus neht ffilC
.moc tod rettiwT morf triD yb uoy rof daer ,gnoS lA yb
esuoh a droffa reve ot elba eb d’I fi wonk t’nod I ,naem I ,oN“
ekil tlef syawla dah I dna
,tekcit eht s’taht hO“
.paC ,emoclew er’uoY“
,elihw a neeb s’tI …tsuj I ,oN“
”.yxes si ytsedom kniht I tub ,ecnedifnoc ekil elpoep tol A“
,em dekrow eh sa loop eht fo egde eht no smra ym detser I
”.fo erac nekat tned taht teg nac I yllufepoH“
.erom elttil a pu desserd ev’dluohs I ebyaM“ .deilper eh
,strohs sih ni eglub eht ffo gniwohs pu doots dna
”.sllib era tuoba yrrow ot evah I lla os rof diap lla si esuoh ehT“
dekcub ylsuoicsnocnu I sa
.thgirla saw ti lufknaht saw dna enohp ym tuo dellup I
naem uoy od ’,laer‘ yB“ ”.laer dna
.htaenrednu eet cihparg a htiw trihs nepo na dna strohs ni retto eht was dna
”.yawa ti evag taht gniht eht saw hctorc ym gnilgo
”.oot ,ylecin raer ruoy sguh tI
.enohp eht hguorht nirg sih raeh dluoc I dna
,pihsnoitaler ruo ni rentrap a naht tnerap a ekil erom tlef eh dias eH
”.pag ega eht ot eud uoy fo egatnavda gnikat m’I ekil ro
,stnetnoc sti dennacs dna unem sih denepo retto ehT
,em ta dekrims eH
”,neht delttes s’ti ,lleW“ ”…tsuj I
.tnemom yrev taht ta emac ev’dluoc I dna
.nalp htlaeh s’dad ym no llits saw I lufknaht saw I .tuo dekcehc dna
nwod dna pu daeh ym gnibbob detrats neht I
,pot emosdnah gib a er’uoy ekil
”?ekil skool eh tahw ees
,egde eht no tas I sa dias I
”?pu s’tahW“ ”…tub
.aera nwotnwod eht fo sklawedis nevenu dna dekcarc eht hguorht yaw ruo edam ew sa egangis dellud htiw serots elttil eht derimda eH
.srobhgien fo tros er’ew sseug I
ttub ym morf pirg sih devom neht dna
”,mM“ .raer ym eporg ot nwod wap sih evom mih tlef dna dias I
gnieerf sfeirb dna strohs ym deppord I
,esruoc fO“ ”?uoy etsat ,hu
.elihw a ni yppah siht neeb t’ndah I dna
.esolc em dellup dna dias eh
”.tuoba tnedifnoc leef yllautca ot gnihtemos deen tsuj I ebyaM“
”.gnizama sleef taht ,n’paC
”.elihw ni etad a no neeb t’nevah osla I
.gnol os rof htaerb sih dloh dluoc eh taht tcaf eht htiw gnola ffo em gnikcus elihw retaw eht rednu gnihtyreve ees dluoc eh ykcul os saw eH
.wap rehto ym htiw cas sih dekrow neht I
,wonk uoy ,hu ,I naC“
,retaw eht fo egde eht no
.puc cimarec ym ni pihc eht ta gnikool dias I
,trohs dna ybbuhc saw eH
*** .ssentiw a dah I tsael ta tub
”,gnizama kool uoY“
thgir ym ot reed fo teelf a deciton neht I .deganam I tub
.mih sdrawot gniggoj detrats I dna
.yllaudividni sehcaep
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.suoivbo taht ti ekam dluow eit a no gnittup ezilaer t’ndid I“ ”.etad a s’tI“
”?sweivretni yna deviecer uoy t’nevaH“
.wam ym otni kcub ot nigeb mih tlef I sa retsaf bob ot nageb I
,odeeps eht nwod dellup dna dnuora denrut eH
.raewrednu ym ni erusserp tlef I ylneddus dna
.enot delffum a ni dias I
.rehto eht htiw tonk ym dniheb em dezeeuqs dna
.eruces llits erew kcab eht ni sexob eht erus edam dna em dniheb dekcehc neht I
,tsap eht morf pu gnihtemos thguorb I nehw ti detah syawla eh dna ,hgU .dnim t’ndid I tub
.detaudarg I retfa krow yna dnif t’ndluoc I tub
,dias eh ”,haeY“ ”?kcod tahT“
.tfahs dna tonk ym htiw gniyalp nageb eH
,noisicerp elbidercni htiw retaw eht otni evod neht eH
.detnaw I tahw wenk ydaerla I tub
.em ot txen gnittis sa deksa eh
gnittis mih was I
.seilleb ruo neewteb nwod neht
”,ybraen tnaruatser esenapaJ doog ytterp a s’erehT“
.dnabtsiaw sih fo citsale eht rednu ti decalp dna tsirw ym ot
.nwot eht ot tfig elbidercni na saw
,em erofeb duts sselwalf eht morf yawa ezag ym kaerb ot tluciffid osla saw tI
thgis tcefrep a hcus ssentiw ot tog I revenehw tub
redluohs sih no daeh ym detser I
.dekaeuqs I ”,haey ,heH“
.rebmem suomrone sih woleb gnuh sllab yvaeh owt sa nikserof sih fo tuo gnikeep snalg sih fo elttil a ees dluoc I
.delworg dna denaom eh sa elzzum ym dedoolf dees sih nooS
.loop eht ni sgel sih gnikcik yltneg
.tfel eht ot elttil a devruc ti dna