saw sihT     .reh dlot eh
.retal sraey owt seires noisiviD gnoL sih gnitirw nageb dna
,delkcuhc raeb ehT
,enaiD  .reh ot sgnoleb ereht revo kcirtaP
,htuom sih fo tuo gnignah eugnot s’ycarT deciton ehs nehw tuB
”?etag eht hguorht ni og tsuj dluohs ew kniht uoy oD“
sgniws eht denodnaba dah spup eht erehw
.nosinu ni dias seninac llams eht ”?tahW“
”,yddad ym saw uoy dehsiw I“
”.lrig yadhtrib eht ot olleh yas og s’tel woN“
”.etal oot ton s’ti ebyaM“
htrof dna kcab gnippoh saw ycarT erehw
.ten.ytiniffaruf no seirots ’susrU fo
,edaced a naht erom retfA
”!uoy ot yadhtrib yppah
”.em rof gnihtemos od ot evah uoy ,od I erofeb tuB“
”ooooowO“ gnol eht otni ti gninrut
dehgual etoyoc eht ”!ykniP ,ereht yeH“
”,enigne 71-B a naht strap erom sah gniht gnaD“
mra s’yoR fo dloh koot ycarT
.tuo deppets yksuH elamef a dna denepo esuoh eht morf rood kcab ehT
”.raeB giB ,no emoC“  .etoyoc eht dias
fo edahs mrofinu a erew sdap eot eht fo llA
onarpos teews s’enaiD morf
”?degnahc ti emoc woH“
.redlo tog I nehw roloc degnahc ti tub“
ylgnitivni shgiht sih fo spot eht dettap eH
”.yob doog a s’eH
.ekac eht fo pot no seldnac fo tetrauq eht gnihsiugnitxe ,drah welb neht
knip saw eot tselttil reh no dap ehT
.seldnac eht gnithgil detrats dna
,gnihgual ycarT raeh dluoc stluda rehto eht ,dray eht ssorca morF
”?taht saw nehw ,hO“
.keehc sih no ssik a ycarT evag dna denrut acisseJ
.guh etanoitceffa s’dlihc eht denruter eh sa
tes gniws eht drawot derutseg yoR
”.flesreh yb lla ti did ehS  .epoN“  .yoR deksa
.ytsuD dias ”,deirram teg dluow ycuL dna eh kniht ot desu I“
.deralced eh ”,oot ti ees nac I“
.ylduol dereehc dna
dray eht ssorca detniop ytsuD
.retsgnuoy a saw etoyoc eht nehw emitdeb ta ”elipgod“
.sriaffA ylimaF :ycarT
.noitarepsaxe htiw ycuL dias ”!yddaD“
”,ton yhw ees t’nod I“  .yoR deksa
.daeh sih fo pot eht dessik dna
koob eht morf tprecxe na si elat sihT
.detats ehs ”,ereht ni knip elttil a ees nac I“
”!yako ,yakO“  ”!no emoc ,haeY“
”.od I naht seye retteb evah tsum owt uoy
.dehgual ydobyrevE
”,tsrif tuo ycarT raew ot gniog era seno gnuoy esoht ekil skooL“
,tes gniws eht ot kcab nar yeht sa spup eht detnahc ”!eM  !eM  !eM“  ”?sgniws eht no og annog s’ohw ,woN“
”,oot saw I hsiw I“
”ykniP“   yojne esaelP
ssarg eht ni dellor sdlo-raey-ruof eht sa ”!elipgoD  !elipgoD“
ssetsoh sih detcerroc raeb eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
4102 ni modnaf yrruf eht derevocsid ohw
.etoyoc eht fo pot no derebmalc yeht sa thgiled htiw gnilaeuqs erew dna
.deksa ehs ”?pal ruoy no tis I naC“
.yksuH eht delggig ”!ynnuf s’tahT“
detaes saw ehs erehw morf pu decnuob acisseJ
selpmas erom dnif nac uoY
ega emas eht tuoba fo yksuH elam a dna acisseJ
dias eh ”,eno siht saw tI“
”.hguoht ,gnuoy uoy gnipeek eb ot thguo eno elttil tahT“
,sotcrA susrU yb ”ykniP“ si
”,retfa erom emos yalp ll’eW“
kcen s’eninac redle eht dnuora smra reh tup ehS
.waptoof s’ycarT dehcuot ylraen eson sih litnu
,selam htob desserdda ycuL
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.noisserpxe s’etam sih ta elims tub pleh t’ndluoc yoR
,dray kcab eht otni deppets stseug devirra ylwen eht sA
.niaga dna niaga draob gnidils llams eht edir ot selcric ni gnicar erew
.elims ediw a htiw raeb eht deksa
.ssarg eht no tis ot noitisop sih detfihs etoyoc ehT
.dias ytsuD ”,wonk I ,wonk I“
.acisseJ dednamed ”!ees emmeL  !ees emmeL“
.yoR htiw pihsnoitaler laer sih dna ytilauxesomoh s’ycarT fo erawanu yllufssilb llits saw god dlo eht
,denialpxe acisseJ ,rewsna dluoc ycarT erofeB
.spup eht deksa ycarT ”?tahw wonk uoY“
”.tuo meht nrow s’eh retfa uoy ecudortni ll’I
,yek emas eht otni llaf ot deganam stseug eht fo lla yllautnevE
.deretnuoc acisseJ ”!ruof ma I ,hu-
.gnignis nageb ehs ”…uoy ot yadhtrib yppaH“
.ycarT htiw lautir eht gnitaeper erofeb keehc sih dessik dna
.enaiD ot denialpxe yoR
.seldnac ruoy tuo wolb emoc ot emit s’tI  !acisseJ“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.enevretni ot emoc dah emit eht dediced rehtom gnuoy eht
.teef sih ot tog eh sa delims ycarT
.seot s’ycarT tcepsni ot drawrof denael sdlo-raey-ruof ehT
.ylwols yvehC eht fo tuo tog selam htoB
gnirpsffo s’ycuL sa decarb dna
.dad s’ycuL morf ssorca elbat cincip eht ta taes a otni delttes yoR
.llac etoyoc laref a fo
.pal sih no pup eht deksa eh
.yksuH elttil eht dednamed
ylpeed delahni dlo-
.daeh sih koohs ycarT ”,wonk t’nod I“
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.erofeb nees reve dah ycarT ron eh rehtien taht ereht rac rehtona saw erehT
.sgniws eht no kcirtaP dna acisseJ hsup yletanretla ot
ssarg eht no nwod tas pehS-G llams ehT
.noitseuq ni dap eht hcuot ot tuo dehcaer acisseJ  ”.lla s’tahT
.wap s’ycarT ta deggut dna
elbaliava si seires noisiviD gnoL eritne ehT
saw spup eht fo msaisuhtne lufhtuoy ehT
”?ycarT elcnU ,tuo esoht wolb reh pleh uoy diD“
.elihw a rof no yalp ot spup eht dewolla ycuL  ”.si eh ,seY“
”.apdnarg a gnieb evol od I dna“
,elttil saw I nehW“
”?ytsuD ,gniog ti s’woH“
.ycarT detressa ”,huh-
.yadhtrib htneetxis ym erofeb tsuj“
.ycarT dias ”,stnuoc taht lla s’taht dna yadot ruof si ehS“
❖  .etoyoc eht yb dewollof
.nettogrof saw pih tfel sih ni niap eht dna suoitcefni
.snoitcudortni edam ycuL sa
.decnuonna acisseJ ”,ruof m’I“
,rae s’acisseJ otni derepsihw eH
teef sih ot decnuob yksuH eht
”?yoR elcnU dna ycarT elcnU tuohtiw ytrap a s’tahW“
”.emit yna seldnac eht thgil nac eW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.elbat eht ta taes a koot eh sa ycarT dias ”,eruS“
yadot elbuort emos mih gnivig saw yrujni dlo s’ycarT
”.em dna ycuL tem eh woh s’tahT
.oot eot knip a dah I
.moc.skooB-DL morf
,toof thgir sih no eot driht eht gnippat
.tsehc sih ta flesreh dehcnual
,delaeuqs dna deppots ehs ,yaw reh gniklaw ycarT deciton drehpehS namreG elttil eht nehW
resolc ni denael yksuH elttil ehT
.rae reh no kcil gnivol a lrig elttil eht evag eH
dluow ylimaf sih dna ycarT woh fo yrots eht wenk eH
.oga sraey net revO  !hsoG
sotcrA susrU yb
hctam a kcurts ycuL
”!ycarT elcnU  !ycarT elcnU  !eeeE“
”.kaerb a sdeen ycarT elcnU“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.snoinapmoc sti fo sdap kcalb eht ot tsartnoc ni
”,ycuL dna ytsuD nwonk s’eh sa gnol sa tsomla rof ecalp a gnirahs neeb evah I dna ycarT“  ”.ma I naht kooc retteb a si yoR ,sediseB“
.rehtaf reh dniheb pu deklaw ehs sa ycuL dias ”,oot eno doog a s’eH“
”.hctam lla yeht woN
”!eot knip ym fo esuac‘ s’tI“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.yksuH elttil eht deksa
”.emit ni enod reh tog I tub“ ,denialpmoc ytsuD
.esuoh eht fo edis eht dnuora yaw rieht edam elpuoc eht dna
.drehpehS namreG eht dias ”,yako gniog s’ti ,hO“
”.erus rof s’taht ,erom yna pup on t’nia I ,ay llet ll’I“
.etamyalp dezisrevo rieht htiw
.wap rehto s’ycarT debbarg dna
snoitide cinortcele dna kcabrepap ni
.sdneirf reh teerg ot revo dehsur drehpehS namreG elamef ehT
raey-ruof ehT  ”.seldnac ruoy tuo wolb dna
.tnemeerga ni deddon yoR
.flesmih rof ees dluoc eh os dnuora ti detsiwt dna toof nwo sih fo dloh koot ycarT
.tseug ytrap rehtona ot degnoleb ti ,ylbamuserP
deppalc stseug ehT
”.ruof m’I  .kcirtaP m’I“
,dael s’dneirf sih gniwolloF
huN“  .kcirtaP dias ”,ruof gninrut ylno er’uoY“
.pup gnuoy eht delosnoc eh
.eye reh fo renroc eht morf raet a epiw reh ees ot emit ni ycuL ta revo dekool ycarT  .decnuonna ehs
,dias dna enaiD ot denrut eH  .ytsuD devresbo
”.ykniP ,ereh pu poH“
yrots s’yadoT dna
yoR dnuora smra reh dehcterts ehS
”,yoR elcnU“  ”.yoR si siht
,lleW“  .dehgual etoyoc ehT  .nat
hU“  .feilebsid ni yksuH eht dias ”,hu-huN“  ”.oot
.etipser eht rof lufetarg saw ycarT
,sotcrA susrU yb ”ykniP“
,acisseJ raed yadhtrib yppaH…“
.sdik eht htiw gniyalp ereht revo ycarT elcnU s’taht dnA“
.elims daorb a htiw
.ees dluoc dneirf reh os toof thgir reh pu dleh dna
.ekac eht gnici dehsinif I ,ycuL“
eenk eno ot deppord ycarT
”.erif thguac tnemtrapa suoiverp sih nehw ni devom eH“
.ssab gnilbmur s’ytsuD ot
,deksa dna rethguad sih ot denrut god dlo ehT
.tes gniws wolley dna neerg wen a fo noitcerid eht ni dray eht ssorca dellorts etoyoc ehT
.ycarT dias ”,dlrow eht rof ti ssim t’ndluow eW“
”!sgniws eht no su hsuP  !no emoC“
.dnamed thgim eninac redlo siht tahw fo erusnu
.ssensuoires lufyalp htiw seye s’elam llams eht otni dekool dna nwod denael eH
.deneppah tsuj tI“
.elbat cincip eht ta puorg eht nioj emoc ot yksuH eht rof denokceb ycuL
,ytsuD deddon ”,seod ylniatrec ehS“
,eton tsal eht dleh ycarT
.draoba bmilc drehpehS namreG elttil eht depleh dna
,ycuL dias ”,4691 neeb evah tsum tI“  .enaiD deksa
”.sseJ rof rehtegot tes gniws taht gnittup syad eerht tsal eht tneps eH“
wap s’elamef gnuoy eht ekahs ot esor yoR
”?ykniP reh llac uoy emoc woH“
”.keew tsal tsuj ekil smees tI
.ycuL yb yltnatsni deciton erew yeht
”?sseJ ,rof dehsiw uoy tahw em llet uoy lliW“  .derewsna ycarT
”.ti ekam dluoc owt uoy dalg os m’I“
”.yob taht ta kooL“
.esuoh smailliW eht fo yawevird eht otni ubilaM sih denrut yoR
wap eht yb elamef elttil eht koot etoyoc ehT
,ediw werg seye s’yksuH ehT
,ykniP hsiw a ekam woN“
”.tnemegnarra yraropmet a eb ot desoppus saw tI“
”,naem I ,yoR elcnU“
.ega sih gnileef saw 26 ta yoR dna
.’elcnu‘ drow eht no sisahpme detareggaxe htiw ycuL dias
.nwot otni devom tsrif eh nehw pohS vlaS eht ta nwod em rof krow ot desu ycarT“
.deriuqni raeb eht
.ycuL dias ”,gnol oot rof setammoor neeb evah yoR dna eh kniht I“
”.nikpmuP ,retteb od dluoc uoy kniht t’nod I“  .ytsuD devresbo
.elbat cincip eht dnuora deretsulc puorg eht ot reh del dna
6791 rebmetpeS
”.eman ruoy em llet ot evah uoY“  .deksa eh ”?tahW“
.noitseggus eht edam rehtaf reh emit tsrif eht t’nsaw sihT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.enaiD ,dneirf doog ym si sihT“
.s’ycarT no dekcol erew seye reh tub
.dray kcab eht morf gnimoc rethgual dna seciov raeh dluoc yehT
.lrig yadhtrib eht detuop ”,erom emos ycarT elcnU htiw yalp annaw I ,wwA“  ”.seldnac
.tey pu gnivig ton m’I tuB“
.trihs s’ycarT ta deggut acisseJ
”,sseJ sevol eh hcum woh ees ot ysae s’tI“
”?nikpmuP kniht uoy od tahW“