.ti ssorca gnikaerts muc nwo sih fo sniats ekil-tuo-etihw eht ot tnereffidni
.hturt eht saw timda ot detnaw eh gniht tsal ehT
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,trohs gninnur saw emiT
pu til ecaf
,repap siht no A na evah em tel uoy fI“
ksed eht dettap rehcaet ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”,em rof saw ti sa uoy rof doog saw ti rehtag
,rehtie ,regnol hcum tsal t’ndid sfeirb-rexob ehT
,lleW“ .deplug
s’tahT“	         ”?’yrd ni gniog m’I ,wollip a no nwod etib‘ ,yas yeht woh wonk uoy ,dna...dnA“
.drah deplug yrreT	         ”?yako uoY
,tneduts eht otni thgiarts kcoc sih degnulp eh ,dilos kcor
noitca ot noitalletsnoc a sa stod dael esoht gnidaer
.tset ehT .thgir hO...	         ...tcefrep eht osla tub
”!niaga reve t’now
”!ehtylB .rM ,A siht deen
”?huh hU“	         ”.ti htiw em ezimodos yldetaeper uoy elihw ria eht ni ssa ym gnittup
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,regnad taerg ni er’uoy wonk I
.pu ti revoc ot mih ta kcab gnilims
,dias eh ”,owt-ythgie derdnuh ruof egap ot skoobtxet ruoy nrut esaelp ,ssalc
,drawrof dekcub eh emit yreve dnA
”,gniliaf s’APG ym
,gnippils thguoht tnegoc rehtona
ll’uoY“	         .gniyfsitas t’nsaw rewsna eht taht wenk eh neve tuB
tahT“	         .traeh s’yrreT ni lriws latep rewolf a gniubmi selpmid enihsnus dna sworbeye dekrep
,srewsna neve t’nera esehT“
,elbat eht fo dne eht deppirg eh sa tuhs seye sih gnimmals
.sniatruc s’ti ,taht retfA
.eiprahs a no resare na ekil kciht dednirg kcid taht elihw ,rednu tsuj
eH	         ”!esaelP !sey ,dog hO
.erusaelp htiw gnar elohssa sih sa ruf sih hguorht gnitfis sregnif
.detcepxe dah meht fo rehtie naht rekciuq ecart a tuohtiw dedaf ti tub
”sihT roF eM liaF t’noD esaelP“ saw sihT
,elbat eht otno gnibmilc“ ,no tnew eh ”,hu
.mih nihtiw noissap sih dehsaelnu eh elihw hteet sih gnihcnelc
,yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF no eerf rof daer nac uoy hcihw ,”deyolpmenU“
,gnikcilf liat ,roolf eht tih snaej sih
,ffo ti deppils eh dnoces eht
I“	         ”?yteicos ni eulav cisnirtni on sah suluclac woh tuoba nialpmoc t’now uoy dnA“	         ”!niaga
.hgis a htiw thguoht eh
reveN“	         ”?redrah yduts ot uoy llet I nehw kcab klat t’now uoy
,seY“	         .lrig loohcs renni s’yrreT dias
,esle gnihtemos delangis tuo htaerb sih hguohT
,lleW“	         .ksed sih no yltneconni denihs elppa eht sa
.sruoh-retfa eht ni ssecer ekil xes lamirp
,thgit spih sih deppirg dna
,erup fo slwoy rieht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
taerG“	         .deilper eh ”,dekcehc
,deksa rehcaet eht
”...I dna ,nees reve ev’I nosrep tsettoh eht
”,eurt s’ti ,sey
,stnap sih pu dellup ehtylB .rM ,taht htiw
,reffo gnitpmet a s’ti“
,moor eht hguorht gnitarebrever ssa s’yrreT fo selppir eht ,retsaf
.mih kaerb ot hguone ton tub ,nekahs ecnedifnoc sih leef dluoc yrreT
,tuo llup ylwols ot nageb eh
.ecno uoy ot siht reffo ot gniog ylno m’I os
elbat eht fo edis rehto eht ot tohs ti sa hsinif eht gniniur ylraen
,peed mih detartenep erusaelp erup fo sehcni neveS
stsurht eht htiw ti gnimit
sdrawkcab tsurht a dna ekahs pih A
esuaC‘ .taht raeh ot dalg yllaer m’I“
,ti ta tnew yeht regnol eht esor ylno ytisnetni toh-etihw ehT
taht hcaer kcoc s’rehcaet sih tlef eh
.revoc koobtxet tlef ycnaf a ekil nwod nar
,yoj dna noissap fo sraet yrc dlrow eritne eht ekam ot tseuq sih ni laicurc
nehT“	         .teef sih ot esor dna pu sessalg sih dehsup eh
.esirprus htiw dellif won seye tilrats
dnA“	         ”!meht rebmemer ll’I
.ffo s’ti ,esiwrehtO
,rosseforp tcefrep eht tsuj ton etaerc ot stenalp ekil pu denil gnihtyrevE
,sdnoces lareves rof
,snaej ynniks thgiT
,tuo gnikael muc eht leef dluoc yrreT dna
.deppots yrreT ”,sknahT“
.APG sih fo etats tnerruc eht detcelfer yawklaw der deteprac yledurc ehT
ralloc sih ta deggut ehtylB
?llew os pu lla ti enil seitnewt dim sih ni nam a dluoc woh
ydob s’yrreT pu dellif eh erofeb
,rehtegot sdnah sih deppalc
,sregnif sih dekcarc
.ti saw siht dezilaer eh sa
,ti saw siht thguoht eh sa tsuj tuB
,ti tnaem eh ekil mih dekcuf yllaer ehtylB .rM
,yakO“	         .muirotidua eht sserdda ot no kcab noisserpxe nrets a tup dna ,spil sih desrup
bus sih fo htaerb eht
sih fo edistuo eht nwod sregnif sih nar rosseforp eht sa
.efil sih fo erusaelp eht htiw
,ksed eht otni dehgis eh sA
I“	         ....erusaelp latot fo tnemom lufssilb taht ot resolc dnoces rehtona
,tamrof detaluclac a ni peed desserp sregnif
;seye sih hguorht gnissorc straeh
,htaerb sih thguac eh retfa dias rosseforp sih
nworb dna etihw fo sehctolps elihw seye sih derevoc ruf fo sehctap egnarO
,eye edis luftsul a mih evag eh sa aelp sih tuo denaom
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,shgiht derruf wolley
,pu peek yldrah dluoc eh
.yrreT ot kcab nep eht evag dna revo denael
,detlit daeh s’ehtylB
,pirg thgit sih fo taeh eht ni tuo htaerb gnihsuh
:xis-ytfif noitseuQ
dnA	         .ti htrow ylbidercni lla saw ti gniwonk ,gnilims
,decnuob eciov sih ,mih was eh sA
dellac levon ecnamor aipotu elyts naillewrO a no gnikrow yltnerruc si eh
;rekcilf eht was yrreT
;kcab ti delffuhs
.rof depoh reve d’eh gnihtyreve saw ti
,hteet sih hguorht gnissiH
nwod dewols ehtylB .rM
,tuo dellup eh ,yllaniF
,emag sih naht retfos saw ruf sih tub
,ti revo delbmuts eh sa elsia eht otni dekconk gab
.ytiniffAruF ro yrruFoS
”?ffo retaews taht ekat uoy t’nod yhw
lleW“	         ”?yhw tub ,evisneffo ylthgils
,lluks dna rae sih neewteb nep der eht tup ehtylB .rM
”sihT roF eM liaF t’noD esaelP“   :yojne esaelP
looplrihw sti otni pmuj yltpmorp nac eh os
sesseug dnoces fo maerts eht
,suolaej teg thgim ssalc eht fo tser eht ,ti tuoba gniklat trats elpoep fi tub
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,tnegilletni ,sessalg erauqs
,ylkciuq derevocer eh tub ,deppils snihs sih ,llits ,eciwT
peeD	         ”…si yduts t’nac I yhw nosaer eht“ ,dias yrreT
yrreT	         ”?tnedifnoc gnileeF“
,kcid gib eht tsniaga rehtruf spih sih gnihsup
,lleW“	         .deksa ehtylB .rM
,esneffo fo tnih a deilpmi sworbeye sih fo hctiwt a
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.laer rof s’tihs siht wonk mih tel ot ekahs a ssa taht evag eh os
,doog truh ssa sih sa derepmihw yrreT
,ecap sih tpek eh llits tub
.rovref eht rof sniev sih hguorht doolb wen hserf nar taht
,retaews sih gniniager
diD“ .yal kcats eht erehw edis eht ot gnirutseg
.egde eht ffo deppird dna
,metsys sih ni drah gnignir saw lleb loohcs ehT
,yrrebnikceH sucraM yb
eH	         ”.siht tuohtiw ffo koot uoy ,emit tsal
”sihT roF eM liaF t’noD esaelP“
”.edarg ym fo tnecrep evif-ytnewt si siht em llet t’noD“ ni sa ,D
.repap tset elgnis a no nep der sih gnilbbircs
spil sih morf noitcafsitas fo ssih a
,ksed sih ot pu kcab yaw sih edam dna syawyna no meht tup eh hguohT
skeehc ssa sih dedaenk eh ,kcihT
,syaw thgir eht lla ni pu gnisneT
.ni saw dnim s’yrreT rettug eht fo etisoppo eht yletelpmoc os ,elbisnopser ,tsenrae os
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.eloh thgit sih otni gnizag
mih otni rehtruf gnitsurht-inim
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
,won rof tuB .doirep emit sih ot nruter dna
.ecnalab sih tpursid ot ereht saw tfel gnihton litnu
.delggig rehcaet eht
,kcid taht fo erom detnaw eh yldab woh mih dlot
.daeh sih koohs eH	         ”?laeD
ydaerlA	         .edisa riahc eht dekcik neht dna
.demaeb eh ”!boj
,efil ta retsam ssehc a
;eyesllub ylnevaeh
,tnemom a rof peed sllab saw eh litnu
esoht ,gnilbbow srae
,pu detaeh ydob sih
,rettiwT no mih wolloF
delggig ehtylB
,pu daeh sih denarc dna kcab tah sih deppit rehcaet eht ,ksed eht dehcaorppa eh
I“	         .htaerb sih hctac ot thguof eh elihw elbat eht ffo gnignah smra sih
,sivlep sih otni spih elppus s’bus eht deknay rehcaet sih ,retal sdnoceS
,ksed eht otno dehsalps maerts kciht eht dna ,delley yrreT ”!gnimmuc m’I-
rotcurtsni sih fo tnorf ni teehs elbbub eht devaw
.dne gniyfsitasnu na gnihcaer sesseug dnoces-dnoces dna
,dehsuh dna thgil eciov sih ,dias eh
s’yrreT	         ”!ssalc retfa em eeS
,dexaler selcsum sih lla ,taht htiW
”?suovren tib tsael eht ton er’uoY“	         ”.ees ll’ew
.depmuls redluohs siH
elbat eht ffo sresare dna sesac licnep gnikconk ,gnirettij sbmil
”?yrreT“	         .dnah dehcnelc sih morf delpmurc ti fo selppiR
.uoy htiw xes evah ll’I
,muirotidua eht fo mottob eht ta
.gnidnats nam tsal eht s’eh langis a
,waj sih morf srepmihw etuc
.moor eht gnillif gnilffuhs repap
elpirT“	         ”?gnihtyreve kcehc elbuod uoy
yrreT	         .cirbaf eht gnippals ,decnuonna eh
,keehc sih dehctarcs eH
.mitciv sih decreip remmilg sih sa
.rM	         ”.kcitsdray taht htiw ssa ym gniknaps uoy gninigami pots t’nac I...“	         ....htaerb
.daetsni ,elppa na no nwod etib ot tnaw d’I
,tsaf gninrael saw eh raelc saw ti ,dnoces yb dnoceS
,pih thgir eht ,euqilbo eht
.hguone gniod t’nsaw eh ekil mih gninetaerht
,ekil ,er’uoy dna“ ,denihw yrreT
,ewa ni saw yrreT
,lla ta emit on ni dnA
ruoY“	          .ragus sih ot yenoh ekil
,kcid eht ot pmup doolb rehtona
.stibah gniyduts ruoy ssucsid llits t’ndluohs ew kniht t’nod tuB“
.kcab sih ni sehcton eht gniyduts ,seldnah evol sih debbarg dna
.dnA“	         .deksa ehtylB .rM
.rM	          ”.detrats raey eht ecnis reve selppa uoy gnivig neeb ev’I yhw...hu ,si hcihW
:gniteem eciffo eht ekil saw seye eulb yks sih ni remmilg tahT
erutuf eht rof snoitpo mirg sih ,ydaerlA
”.eciohc on evah htob ew
;ekans a ekil delggirw
!seY“	         ”?uoy t’nod ,A siht tnaw uoY“
si ti rof ,rae luferac a eriuqer seceipretsam lufrednow ,etacirtni siH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.delkcac eh ”,evlos melborp ot ysae os si ydob
I“	         -sih fo edistuo eht gnikop tsuj saw pit eht litnu ,retemillim yb retemillim
nehT“	         .taorht sih htaeneb gnik a ekil
rosseforp sih ta derats eH
”!ksed ym no thgir ti tfel
taht ekil deyats eh dnA
!seY“	         ”?thgir ,slicnep nwo ruoy gnirb ot rebmemer
.gnikool tuohtiw semit erom wef a rotaluclac eht ssorca gnicnad sregnif sih
”!rehtie ,taht od t’nac I
siH	         .tcejbus loohcs tsrow eht si ylurt htaM
.nwod slicnep ,pu seldeeN
eH	         ”!kcid a fo epahs eht otni tset eht deteehs elbbub tsuj I
;ecnelis eht skcarc elbat eht no kcalc nedoow eltbus A
,dias eh ”,flesruoy gnihcuot uoy tuohtiw muc uoy ekam nac I fI“	         ”?yllaeR“
,yrrebnikceH sucraM yb
.od d’eh gniht tsal eht s’ti fi ,ti teg d’eh
.A eht uoy evig ll’I neht“
sA	          .egelloc ni raey eromohpos ta secnahc sih gnibmob erofeb peels s’thgin lluf a dah tsael ta ev’dluoC !hsiloof woh...erow
.esle gnihtyreve ekil tsuj ecafrus eht gnittih yldetbuodnu
wodahs sulumuc a ekil dewolf daerd fo evaw taht
yrrebnikceH sucraM yb
,hguoht ,od ot evah d’tI
:stniop erusserp eht
.ylkciuq sa tsuj tuo neht
,dias eh ”,riaf eb ot
.msinoitibihxe fo swolb dna seow eht tuoba seirots trohs citore rehto ynam htiw gnola
tuB“	         ”.merah dnoces a gnihcaet eb ot si deen I gniht tsal eht dna
dnA“	         .ti gnippots gnihton saw ereht ,gninnur tog htuom taht nehW .thgil neerg
,dog yb dna ,erom rof gniggeb
.potelbat eht otno delbmarcs eh sa stcejbo dna srepap edisa gnihsup
,redrah dekcub rosseforp sih :mehyam
.sdnoces erem ni msagro elbidercni na gninetaerht kcoc drah sih ,pu gnitaeh
”,ehtylB .rM ,ees uoy
.rM	         ”!pots t’nod esaelP“
.keehc eht no mih dessik neht
”!?yllaeR“	         ”.oot ,etuc ytterp erew uoy thguoht syawla ev’I“
...erow eh retaews knip dna nat ,der ykcul eht gnisruc
,seye sih revo tah sih deppit ehtylB .rM
.ecanruf a ot dehsulf ecaf sih dna dekoorc tnew sessalg sih sa
,noitatiseh oN	         ”?og ot tnaW
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.neht detcartsid yllaer dekool uoy thguoht I ,yrreT ,yltsenoH“
tuB“	         ”.tset ruoy ni ssap tsuJ
.noitacol rieht morf yawa syawllah morf tlef eb dluoc egnirc fo sllihc eht litnu
,ecneitap sih saw os dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.emit
.tsixe reve ot rohtua tsetaerg eht ylevitcejbo dna xof yrutnec ht91 a — si eh stsisni ohw —  si ohw
,tnemom a rof tsuj dna ,detnurg ehtylB .rM
uoY“	         ”.em htiw ti thguorb I erus rof thguoht I .ynnuf s’tahT“
.sregnif sih ni nep der eht gnilggiw
,elbat eht ffo debmilc seenk kaew sih sa
;keew tsal ssalc eht rof seikooc fo hctab naem a dekooc
.dehctip hgih ,dehtaerb yrreT
.tsif sih ni srepap eht gnilpmurc ,deggeb yrreT
”,srehto eht lla htiw pot no seog
.no tnew emit sa tnerappa erom emaceb ylno ti dna
.naom a ticile ot hguone peed
,daeh sih hguorht nar
.deknilb yrreT	         ”.pu ssa ruoy tuP“
.taht ekil reerac ym ksir t’nac I“