?kool neve I tsum woH ?neve
?sniatnuom eht no nwod kool I lliW
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ydob ym gnivael luos yrev ym tub
.wonk t’nod tsuj I os ,)?thgir
dereffid ti yaw eht
ria eht hguorht ,rehtona neht
ti tuoba od ot ereht si tahW
.em morf yawa nrut ll’yeht syawla dna
.dnecsed ylpeets ot nageb htap reh sa dehctaw I dna
,goD fo ecioV ehT no
eltserw ecaf reh dehctaw I
,spahrep ,elbmuts ll’yehT .em egdelwonkca ot elbanu era yeht
.sraef tsrow dezilanosrep htiw secaps knalb eht gnillif noitanigami nwo s’eno ni ,yas thgim emos sa ,eil ton seod rorroh eht tuB
,floWcaM boR yb daeR
.esruc reh detirehni evah I
.tey ti wonk t’nseod ylpmis dna
.rehtie ,stif siht kniht t’nod I
.sdoow eseht ,sliart eseht gnitnuah ma I
,sdoow eht ni tuo gnihtemos
.swalc nwo ym rof decaps yltcefrep
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”pU kooL esaelP“
?em fo selpitlum ni dnuorg eht ot ecnatsid ym erusaem ot elba ma I ,stoor dna skcor
?deliaf eciov ym dna
noom fo tnilg eht
.ton tcepsus I ?tsol kool I oD
,krad saw ti ton ro rehtehw
,enim tem ehs sa ezag reh ni ytip was I
.eromyna egaugnal eldnah neve t’nac I .bos-
,yhw snosaer tuohtiw
.rebmemer regnol on I eman esohw niatnuom a pu yawflah
,won liart suonimun erom emos tsniaga hcnurc sdap yM
.daeh liart eht si ti spahrep ,nwod sepols ti fI .timmus eht si laog eht spahrep ,pu sepols htap eht fI
.eb-ton-dluoc dna eb-ot-dah neewteb pag eht ,ymotohcid taht yb denifed ecaps eht otni nwod nellaf yletaidemmi dah dna ,ngis eht daer dah I
.rekihhctih flowerew
,kcabhctiws eno koot htap reh sa dehctaw I .yrrac ot
,deye-dliw m’I spahreP
,snoitanalpxe tuohtiw
ees ton dluoc I liart a dednuop
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ytisoiruc fo htrow s’reksihw a flah htiw enoyna sa
.em tsniaga pmub neve t’nod yeht taht hcus
,nommoc tsom eht si siht dna ,rO
ymotohcid eht htiw
,oot ,I litnu gnol woH
,eb dluohs I sa saw ohw eno eht saw I ?dnuorg eht no ereh ,em ta hgual ria eht ni pu teef ytnewt eno dluoc woH !dehgual ehS
,flesym ot siht yas I
,kool ot nrut ll’yeht dna noitnetta rieht hctac lliw
daer tsrif dah I nehw kcab saw thgiarts thguoht d’I emit tsal eht spahreP
,evoba raf revewoh ,em sees dna ria eht ni pu skool loof roop emos litnu
.pets yreve htiw lleb a ekil sgnir taht ssenitpme taht
.enots dna dum neewteb yawflah seil taht trid taht
.gnol woh swonk ohw ni emit tsrif eht rof
.shtap fo gnihcnarb eht tsap tsuj eert eht ot delian ,ereht
taht tub ,ih gniyas tuohtiw em dnuora klaw yeht taht tsuj ton s’tI
,niaga gnivil ta ecnahc ym ssim I tsel ,dna gniklaw peek tub od ot ereht si esle tahW
?gniklaw peek tub od ot ereht si tahw ,neht litnu dnA
,nrut ni tsohg ylenol a was dna snevaeh eht ot pu dekool dna noitinomda eht derongi I esuaceb tsohg a ma I
?etats eht no nwod kool I lliW
!ton dluohs ehs sa saw ohw eno eht saw ehs dna
,em evoba mussop eht was I
,dias dah ngis eht ,pu kool t’noD
ecap citnarf a htiw emoc t’nseod taht enigami I
,eurt t’nsaw ti hguoht ,dna
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
sklaw ohw xof eht ma I
.thgil si trihs ym ,kciht si taoc ym ,looc saw rehtaew ehT ?sretemolik neT ?thgir ,ekih ruoh-owt a rof hguone eb dluow taht yleruS
,gnineppah sgniht eht fo gnidnatsrednu on gnivah fo raef ehT
.dniheb ylthgils os reve sllaf eno sa
,dnuorg eht gnirettil sevael nepsa emas eht ,htap emas eht fo derit worg ylkciuq I
gniklaw neeb evah I
mrof derohcna taht morf
.em ot gninaem lla tsol sah ,egaugnal sa llew sa ,emiT
”pU kooL esaelP“   yojne esaelP
?enots emas eht taht saW
,em ot ygolopa tnelis a dehtuom ehs ,ecaf reh nopu detniap ytip htiw ,sa dehctaw I
?ees neve I lliw tahw dnA
?dnatsrednu dna yrt yhW
.hteet prahs hguorht dessih sesruc tfos ro
.tsohg a ekil kool I ,oN .sknurt gnidnats-thgiarts neewteb ylsselmia gnitfird ton ma I dna
?hguoht ,siht tuoba gnikniht rehtob yhW
sekih rieht no tuo srehto taht yaw eht
,sruoh eht kcehc ot yks eht otni pu kool t’nac I .spahrep ,snezoD ?hguoht ,elkcunk-
.sllaftoof nwo ym fo derit worg ylkciuq I
?citcelaid ro ymotohcid a
,srewsna tuohtiw ,nwonknu eht fo yrots a stneserp
.ekoj a eb ot dah tI
.gniyrc gnol os tneps gnivah morf seye ym ni gninrub eht fo derit worg I dna ,ria eht ni seldeen enip gniyaced ylwols fo tnecs eht fo derit worg I
,hteet prahs yb erom ecno detag gnieb erofeb
.pu kool ot eno detivni tub lla
,esirprus a eb t’nthguo ti hguoht ,reh was I dnA
?lluf-flah llits elttob retaw ym si yhw ,syad neeb sah ti fi tuB
?thguoht ni tsol ma I hguoht sa kool I oD
won neve rac ym erehw ot htap eht nwod delbmuts dna
.em gnigdelwonkca tuohtiw em dnuora reets
ton yldetniop yreV .nwod gnikool
,trid emas eht ni snoitatnedni emas esoht gnivael swalc emas esohT .htap dekcap-drah emas taht gnittih
.reh hguorht yks eht fo eulb eht ees dluoc I denigami I
.ekoj a neeb evah ot dah tI
?ytip dna feiler dna niap ni peew em stel dna ,seye ym steem
:sgninaem rieht enivid yllanif lliw I spahreP
?ti dluoc ,eb t’ndluoc tI .ton saw ti
.meht tsniaga pu hsurb t’nod I taht os
.ria eht hguorht gniklaw ,gnipmots
.ekil kool I tahw wonk I .siht flesym gniksa m’I yhw wonk t’nod I
?thgir ,eb ot dah tsuj tI
.rorre ym fo ecnedive si tahT .tsohg a ma I
.enots flah ,dum flah si taht trid eht tned regnol on swalc yM
,ereht was dna pu dekool I
saw sihT      .pu kool esaelp
.sliart lla fo dne eht ta syal sseltbuod taht peels lanif
.no dekramer llew si nwonknu eht fo rorroh ehT
hcum woh rettam oN .eb ot
.efil ni esoprup delliflufnu emos rof gniregnil ton ma I dna ,evol denrups emos yb ecalp siht ot deniahc ton ma I
.eson ym nihtiw nrub ti leef dna htaerb yreve ym no htaed eht etsat nac I
edis eht ot hcrul ll’yeht dna ,teltoor gnidniw a ni thguac ro enots dednuor a ssorca gnirettiks swalc
,elkcunk-toor dehsilop-toof emos no
,sdniw neesnu yb deteffub ro nrot ton ma I
enim won saw erob ehs esruc revetahw taht su neewteb dessap egdelwonk nekopsnu eht dna
teef reh sa neve saw ehs daed woh tsuj was
,evil yam ehs taht os deid evah I
,hteet dettirg hguorht gnitnap
.em morf nekat saw htaerb nwo ym ,efil fo htaerb eht dehtaerb dna htrae ot nwod deppets ehs sa neve dna
.neeb evah tsum tI
.dewot neeb ydaerla t’nsah ti fi ,dekrap saw
.taolf I hcihw nopu liat ypsiw a htiw decalper neeb ton evah sgel yM .tneculsnart ton m’I .taht sa luficnaf os gnihton si tI .on ,yltsohg toN
,esaelP ?pu kool ton
.liart siht tnuah I dna
,wolloh esoht fo eno ekil kool I
tuo evag selcsum ym nehw
ria eht hguorht gniklaw reh was I
,gnidnecsa gnol os retfa gnidnecsed htiw
,nepsa htiw elgnim senip erehw ,secalp lla fo ,ereH
,eb tsum I( selcric ni gniklaw m’I fi kcehc ot em dnuora kool ron
,rehto eht neht dna eno seod ti ,syawla sa ,fI
teef deddap emas esohT
?aes eht ssorca depollag sesroh knip taht naem ti did tahW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.trihs ym fo tnorf eht nwod dna nihc ym gnikcelf elttips
,owt tsael ta rof
ezeerb ro mihw emoS
rorre ym fo ytimrone eht neht tuB
,t’nsi ti litnu raeb ot enim si siht taht wonk I tub
,gniklaw neeb dah ehs gnol woh wonk t’nod I
,spoteert eht fo level eht ta pu
.ecnalab reh peek reh pleh ot taht dna yaw siht dettilf liat sselruf reh dna kcab detnac srae knip-deniats-kcalb reh sa serutaef esoht ni tserc ,ytip
,sey ,tsohg a ma I ?pets yreve htiw
,noitome driht a dehctaw I neht dnA
?spahrep ,lamron kool llits I oD
,I dnA .pu kool t’noD
nwonknu eht fo rorroh eht ,oN
?naeco eht ot tuo kool I lliW ?yrtnuoc ehT
.htrae ot seert gnirohcna stoor enip delrang emas eht
,eromyna gnillet on saw erehT
.ekoj a eb t’ndluoc tI
flah-hgual-flah a nwod ekohc I ?teef yM ?swap ym ereW
pu dekool I .pu dekool I oS
.retaw fo retil flah a dna yaw eht gnola seirolac wef a naht erom yna deen t’ndluow I
.ereh tuo neeb ev’I syad ynam woh wonk t’nod I taht tcaf eht redisnoc ,rO
,ezilaer I ,won dnA
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,laog eht ot no eunitnoc ot deen ylpmis yeht swonk dna derit si ohw thgim eno sa
.dnuorg eht naht rehto gnihtemos ta kool dluow tsol si ohw enO
,secneuqesnoc on gnitsil ngis A ?pu kool toN
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.sesarhp owt eht otno rehto eht ro drow eno etsap ot deirt d’I semit ynam woh rettam on
luos ym dekconk dna em otni dehsarc
,taht saw oga gnol woH .ngis eht
dna trid eht ot nwod kool yllauteprep I sa ,litnu gnol woH ?dnuorg eht ffo
.sdrow elpmis eerht esoht yb
?spoteert eht fo level eht ta klaw
— ekaL daehworrA ees I lliW ?sehcnarb fo skoorc ni stsen rieht gnikam yks eht fo sdrib eht ees I lliW
eugnot ym gnola gnillor sdrow esoht etsat I hcum woh
.shtnom lla fo rebotcO nI
.no doots I eno eht sa laer sa sselehtenon saw hcihw tub
,rebmemer I esuaceb
— liart eht tem teef reh neht dna
,I naht laer erom raf gnihtemos
.dnuorg eht hcuot regnol on teef ym
,ekatsim ym fo ssenlluf eht ylno ton tnemom taht ni tlef dna
etis reh no elbaliava
.kool ot diarfa m’I ,wonk t’nod I
?seldeen fo sdeb ni stsen rieht gnikam dnal eht fo stsaeb llams eht ees I lliW
,lortnoc on gnivah fo
.rekihhctiH flowereW
?thgir ,pu kool t’noD
.dnatsrednu ot yrt ot
.taht ylesicerp did
elif elgnis otni tuo nethgiarts ylneddus lliw ,edis yb edis gniklaw ,elpuoc a ebyam rO
smeop dna ,seirots
,gnidaert erugif a
goD fo tsohG eht thginot oS
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”pU kooL esaelP“
.tsom naht erom tub emos naht ssel sknuks sekil ohw
.ytilaer renniht emos morf teprac der emos ekil em erofeb tuo sllor ecnedive eht ,liart eht gnola pmats dna pmots I sa neve dna
tsinogatorp ruo dna uoy htob rof
pih ym tsniaga gnihsols ti leef llits I od yhW
.dehgual ehs dna daed eht fo seye eht tem dna pu dekool I .pu gnikool
,elbativeni taht si laog eht spahrep neht
.nwonknu si ti taht si
,llec terces yreve ni ssenwolloh taht leef nac I
.won dnuorg eht ffo sehcni ma I
,htrae eht ni stned ruof esoht ,ti ediseb ,erehT
.si taht revetahw
.elttob retaw a dna ykrej fo tib a em htiw thguorb dah I ?retaW ?doof dnA
edisniatnuom siht ,doow siht ,liart siht ot derohcna m’I
doolb si ereht spahrep dna ,hcnelcnu dna hcnelc swap derruf-kcalb spahreP
’citcelaid‘ dna ’ymotohcid‘ ereW
dah tI .eb ot dah tI
,tsohg ylenol a sees dna snevaeh eht ot pu skool loof roop emos litnu tiaw tub
,ecaf reh nwod gnimaerts sraet eht was
?htrae eht fo evruc eht ni doG ees I lliW
taht ro yaw siht hsiws sliat rieht gnikam elcsum fo hctiwt suoicsnocbus ro
daed eht fo seye eht tem dna
.seilpmi taht naht repeed s’tI
— doots I hcihw no liart derohcna eht
.ecnedive lanif eht si tahT
ehs ylneddus dna
?citcelaiD ?ymotohciD
,gniklaw neeb ev’I gnol woh wonk t’nod I
.leef I sa dekcinap sa kool I spahrep rO
,ecnatsni rof ,si erehT
,daed saw I dna evila saw
.tsohg a ekil kool I
.sngis era ereht ,taht dnoyeB
?nisrap ,leket ,enem ,enem yhW
.ria deiferar eht ni ereht ,htaed ot ezeerf I sa neve nus eht fo taeh eht ni pu nrub dna htaerb rof elggurts dna psag I dna gnihton ot sniht ria yrev taht ro
elbignat ssel gnihtemos
gninraw a eugav os erob taht ,tnemecrofne on
.kni.oykam ta
teef ma I litnu gnol woH
deid sah ohw klof ytpme
.htob saelp dna sesruc yrrac hteet dehcnelc neewteb shtaerb dessih esohw xof eht ma I .sklaw dna sklaw dna
— ton od I ?laog a dah I nehw rebmemer uoy oD !laog ym
.ecnedive si ,oot ,tahT
,skoob lareves sah ehS
.daed gnieb fo sraey ro skeew ro syad ynam os retfa evila gnimoc fo
semoc taht selcsum fo ehca neddus eht ta feiler dna niap fo )?citcelaid(
.nus eht fo taht naht gnirevlis sti ni
?skaep eerht neewteb tsen sti gnikam
?liart eht no sruoh detnuocnu ym ni smaerd ees I lliW
si yrots s’thginoT dna
.sdap hguorht desserp ev’yeht erehw swalc esoht gniniats
,sliart eht gnola gnipmats ,gnisirprus yaw on ni ,xof A
.woleb htrae gnirohcna eht naht laer erom dna
,gninethgiarts kcab ,gnikrep srae
naem ti did tahw
?od ot desoppus I saw esle tahW
.yhw gniwonk ton fo
toor taht nees I dah semit ynam woH