.revo dekool eh emit yreve tnemeticxe dna raef fo egniwt thgils a htiw gninediw seye sih ,elbissop revenehw gge eht no deniamer
.gge eht ta nwod gnikool
.efil reh fo tuo teg ot gniyrt nigeb neve ot erehw gnirednow ,seye reh desolc ehS
”.em rof ytiC ocixeM ot ffo s’ti
,ybab reh llits yletamitlu saw ti
”.tsrif ti tuoba kniht ot deen d’uoy detcepxe I ,yltsenoH“
esiwrehto tub ,erew selacs s’notsnarC eht naht rethgil elttil a erew selacs siH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
lausunu saw gnihtemos nwonk evah dluohs eh ,thgisdnih nI
”.yadot myg eht ta
”!elbaroda er’uoy ,hO“
----**---- .hguorht dekeep tsuj
”.dlrowrednu lanimirc eht fo trap llits era uoy elihw
”.elbissop sa suoitneterpnu sa gnieb tuoba lla si ehS“
?od ot tahw wonk eh dluow woH
.nosillA ot dekool neht eH
,ecalp ni ezeerf selcsum sih tlef eH
?thgir ,emitemos ukufomoM yb gniws
,deppots yletaidemmi cisum ollec ehT
,tekcaj tius reh ot tnew neht ehS
.rotabucni eht ot revo decnalg eh sa nehctik eht revo gnitfaw
”?tnaw uoy od tahw ,thgirlA“
.dlrow taht ni toN
.tahwemos denediw seye s’aterG
.meht rehtag ot yrt ot tfel saw eh dna ,gninefaed tsomla saw erutraped reh fo ekaw eht ni moor eht ni ecnelis ehT
:meht fo tnorf ni tup dah eh tahw ta nwod gnikool dna noops reh gnivaw ,siht ta delims nosillA ”…wonk I“ ”!tuo lla tnew yllaer uoy ,raed ,kciredoR
rovalf laerec eht yaw eht gnirovas dna etib a gnikat
wehpen sih yb tseb sih od ot dednetni eh dna
.smra sih evom ot elba yllanif
.dias eh ”,seY“ .deddon kciredoR
emit siht tsael tA
emoh retteb a edivorp dluoc kciredoR erus saw ehs elihW
.mih ot klat ot gnipoh yletarepsed mih ot emac ohw
,kciredoR ot denrut neht ehS
”!emoh tog I nehw denoitnem uoy taht yadot boj a rof deksa ohw esroh taht tuoba kniht ,lleH“ .deggurhs ehS
”.yltsenoh ,tib elttil a rof ti tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’I“
,notnA htiw dehsinif eh retfa nur yrecorg a no og ot evah dluow eH
,thgin eritne eht tser ot deen did tI
,rotabucni eht ot revo teg ot gnilbmarcs sih nI
”.gnihton rof ereh tuo emoc evah em ekam t’nod esaelP“
,uoy ot klat ot detnaw I os
,kciredoR ot esolc ni denael ehs ,siht htiW
,ffo thgin eht dednuor dah
”.notsnarC sacuL elttil ,dlrow eht ot emocleW“
”!gnihctah s’eh kniht I ,nosillA“
,etalp eht no tes d’eh attoc annap fo pirts eht otni gniknis saw noops s’nosillA taht won ,llitS
saw sihT .yltneg gnisserp dna yawflah swalc gnibbarg sih gniteem ,tuo regnif a dednetxe ehS .nosillA sdrawot
.ybab elttil eht morf sprihc fo seires teiuq tahwemos a htiw tem
”,yksir oot s’tI“ .dias eh
,dnik a tog ev’uoY“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?ew od ,remraw gnitteg ti tnaw t’nod eW
.ni yaw sti peerc ot gnitrats noitasrevnoc taht tlef eh
.ti tuoba kniht tub pleh ton dluoc eh
.myg eht ot tisiv s’aterG fo ffo dnim sih tpek ti tsael tA
,niaga delahni eH ”…dnA
Y“ .ylduol rehtar gnilffins ,deddon aterG
.htaenrednu dap gnitaeh a ees yltniaf dluoc
.attoc annap eht otni kcab noops reh gud ehS .deilper nosillA ”,og uoy erehT“
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffaruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
eht nI .gab eht denepo aterG ,neht dnA
.dehctah ti nehw enola ybab eht tnaw ton did yeht
:kcolc eht ta pu decnalg kciredoR
.yaw eht fo tuo seirtnasaelp eht teg dluoc yeht os ydaerla hctah dluow ti dehsiw mih fo traP
.rehtaf eht ot esolc t’nsaW“
.yltneg gge eht gnittep ,dehgis ehS
erus edam eh rood eht desolc kciredoR sa noos sa dna
.no kcab sessalgnus reh dellup ehs ,siht htiW
.gnippots taorht sih tlef llits eh niaga ni dehtaerb eh emit eht
er’ew neht ,thgirlA“
”,esruoc fO“ .deddon kciredoR
yletaciled erom raf mih dleh ehS
sey yas yletamitlu dluow kciredoR depoh ehs elihw dna
,mih fo tnorf ni saw ti taht won dna
,pu doots yletaidemmi nosillA
”.taht ekil anitsirhC tlusni ton s’teL“ .dias eh ”,oN“
era woH“ .ti ot egde tfos tcnitsid a saw ereht tub ,derebmemer ehs sa ffurg sa saw eciov s’kciredoR ”.aterG“ ”?olleH“
.flesreh deirrac dah ehs woh morf tsuj
,delkcuhc kciredoR
,ytrid rehtar saw moor letoh s’aterG
?ti ot ekat ehs dluow woh dna ,taht tnaw neve ehs
.esruoc fo ,peels gnisol saw ehs yhw ton saw sihT
.ti fo erus saw kciredoR ,boj tsal eno rof
moordeb eht ot esolc pu ti tes dah yehT
”,gge ruoy tuoba nosillA htiw deklat I“ ”?ti si tahW“
.kciredoR ot denrut ehs sa elahxe dereggats a gnivig ,gab leffud eht desolc ehS
.riah a esaercni etar traeh sih gnileef
,rotabucni eht fo mottob eht ta warts eht no tuo dial etaciled os dekool eH
,dnatsthgin eht ot denrut neht ehS ”.yakO“
hsac ni dnif dluoc ehs gniht tsepaehc eht rof gniyap dna
.yltneg dias ehs ”!mih ta kool ,hA“
sregnif reh gniyalps ,delahxe ehS
.mih ta pu dekool ehs sa swalc reh ni stsirw sih gnipsarg
.pu worg mih ees reven thgim ehs taht noitisop a ni flesreh gnittup saw ehs ereh dna
.ot depoh evah reve dluoc eh naht
,saw eh ereht ,noos dna
etalp eht ot kcab gninrut
ehcivec pollacs fo retrats llams a dna
.smra s’nosillA morf elidocorc elttil eht pu gnikcip
,ylwols deddon aterG
.nwod noops sih gnittes
”,sseug I ,retcarahc a sa em ekirts seod sucraM“
.redrah elttil a dnah sih gnizeeuqs
.reh ot tnaem siht hcum woh wenk eH
nehW“ .rennalp reh gnibbarg
.mra eno sih ni ylthgils mih gnicnuob kciredoR
.emoh ta sepicer rieht fo emos gnitacilper dnim ton did eh tub
,aterG retsis degnartse sih yb detpurretni saw eh nehw ,myg eht ta dna yrekab eht ta yad lamron sih tuoba tnew kciredoR ,emit tsaL
.ylefas ereht dehcrep saw edisni saw revetahw taht erus gnikam fi sa tsomla ,hcneb ybraen a no gab leffud eht decalp ylregnig aterG .kciredoR deksa
”,ybab ,uoy ot kcab emoc ll’I ,yademoS“
rebmun enohp a gniees dna pu ti gninepo yletaidemmi ,ti koot kciredoR
”?dnuora emoc ot emit doog a eb dluow
,seye s’rehtom sih sa neerg emas eht enohs yehT
.ti ta dekool eh sa gnilahxe ,hguod fo dnuom eht morf yawa nip gnillor eht dellup kciredoR …retaL htnoM enO
.luos sih otni ecreip ot demees taht seye ediw esoht htiw kciredoR ta pu gnikool
”.snoitpo ruo erolpxe
.eerup odacova nwo sih otni noops sih gud eh sa
.ffo sessalgnus reh gnillup yllanif
.daeh sih koohs eH
.kciredoR dias ”,os sseug I ,haeY“
.kcohs ni gninediw seye sih ,desuap kciredoR
.reduol os reve gnar ycrem taht deined eb thgim ehs ytilibissop eht
----**---- .nosillA ot noitseuq eht kaerb ot kniht dluoc eh yaw eno ylno saw ereht
emoc dluow ti gnileef a dah yeht hguohtla
eht tsriF !evah t’ndluohs uoy ,ssendoog hO“
,taht kcart dluow dlrowrednu eht ni elpoep wonk htob I dna uoY“
.kcarc eht hguorht dekeep tuons ynit a
”,llac ruoy rof gnitiaw eb ll’I“
.reh ot rewsna ot evah dluow eh dnuora ton saw ehs fi neve wenk eh ro
.etib reh dehsinif nosillA
”.elidocorc ybab a ni ekat ot gnilliw eb dluow elpuoc namuh on wonk uoy
,saw ereht ograc fo dnik suoicerp tsom eht saw tI
.smra sih otni mih koot nosillA ,yletanutroF
.ecalp ni nezorf deniamer kciredoR
.sdnah sih ni noisnet emos tuo gnikahs dna gnilahxe ,deddon kciredoR
.denediw seye sih ,dnim sih ni deretsiger sdrow s’nosillA sa noos sa tub ,gnihtemos yas ot htuom sih denepo kciredoR ”!ydaer m’I“
.retaw sih pu kcip ot tnew eh sa ylsuovren gnihctaw notnA
kciredoR dniheb tsuj gniklaw erofeb
,stbuod nwo sih llits erew ereht tuB
,reh ot denrut eh dna ,kcals tnew waj siH
.rotabucni eht fo egde eht no dnah reh gnicalp ,drawrof denael nosillA
,niaga ti denepo ehS
”?ekas ym rof ti gniyas uoy era ro ,ti htiw KO yllaer uoy era tuB“
.kciredoR dias ”,on tub
”—ot em ecrof t’ndluow eh ,efil siht ni kcab tnaw t’nod I swonk eH“ .dias eh
,tcejbo raluvo ,etihw a saw warts eht ni demarf tuB
”.uoy knahT“ .dias aterG
.kciredoR ot ti gnidnah dna repap fo pils llams a tuo gnillup
”,yrekab eht ta enod m’I retfA“
.laeuqs teiuq a tuo tel ot htuom sih denepo eh neht dna
,drawrof denael eh sa
,deirrac ti gge eht ot sa llew sa meht fo owt eht ot gnitrofmoc tsomla devorp dah
.erom elbbow ot gge eht rof emit ni tsuj ,kciredoR ot txen rotabucni eht ta saw nosillA sdnoces fo elpuoc a retfa dna
.ecaf reh fo tuo riah emos gnihsurb ,deddon nosillA ,hguoht ,yllaniF
?eno htiw doog eb eh dluow
,erehwyna epahs taht wonk dluow kciredoR
”.ti tnaw t’ndid ehs fi reh no taht tsiof ot em fo riaf eb t’ndluow ti
.deb eht no tas ehs sa tahwemos gnixaler sbmil reh
.mih ta dekool ehs nehw gnimaeb
:deffocs aterG ,yletaidemmI ”.nosillA ksa em teL“ .dias eh ”,wonk t’nod …I“ .delahni kciredoR .taht tuohtiw esuoh eht otni gge na gard
.daeh sih gnikahs ,delkcuhc rotagilla eht ,ereh dnA .deksa ehs
”?efil taht ni pu worg ot ti tnaw t’nod uoy dnA“ .dias eh ”,ees I“
.mih dniheb ti kcol ot
.deilper aterG ”,oN“
,recrofne bom a ot klat ot ylrae ytiC ocixeM ni ffo eb dluow I resiaK eht dlot I“ .tuo
.yltneg sredluohs sih otni desserp sdnah s’nosillA yaw eht no flesmih gniretnec ,pu tas neht eH
ecitcarp ollec s’nosillA fo dnuos eht ,delahxe eH
”.aterG ,flesruoy fo erac ekaT“ .deilper kciredoR ”,worromot uoy ees lliw I“
,siht ta reduol neve deprihc eH
,rehtegot ,ecaps taht ni ,meht fo eerht eht tsuj saw ereht ,hguoht ,won roF
.dluoc eh sa hcum sa
.deilper kciredoR
.ybab elttil eht sdrawot dnah rehto sih gnignirb dna resolc gninael erofeb
.taht od ot dah ehs yaw tseb eht saw
.sdnah sih ni daeh sih gnicalp dna nosillA morf gninrut ,delahxe neht eH
.ereht ni esle gnihtyna fo hcum neve ro
.esolc ni denael ehs dna ,deddon nosillA
.tsrif ereh ruoted a edam I tub
.tniop doog yllaer a dah ehs ,yllautca taht dezilaer eh
.yawa dekcab aterG dna ,yltnatsni tsomla ecaf reh otno emoc nworf eht was kciredoR
”…dna ,rehtona ot del gniht eno taht deveiler os tsuj erew ew dna ,llew os no tog eW
,skeehc reh nwod gninnur won sraet eht htiw dnA
.yawa htaerb reh koot htuom s’rehtorb reh fo tuo sdrow eht gniraeh neve tub ,esruoc fo ,ti detcepxe dah ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
…gniraer dlihc ot detalsnart taht fi dnA
,troffe erom elttil a retfA
”ograC suoicerP“   yojne esaelP
.lla ta meht evom ton dluoc eh ti delliw eh hcum woh rettam on dna
,drawrof deppets ehs ,deednI
.reilrae reh desserdda dah eh woh ot thguoht eh sa denethgit traeh siH
.deddon eH .dias eh
,tey tsuj dehctah ton
.yaw eht fo tuo seitilagel eht teg
.rotabucni eht ot dehsur yletaidemmi eh ,llitS
,yawa decnalg kciredoR ”?dlareG“
.eireganeM oirT fo rebmem a dna
.mih htiw tsurt I eno ylno eht er’uoY“
.edis eht ot detlit daeh reh dna ,dehsinav yltnatsni elims s’nosillA
,yawa sraet eht fo sniamer eht gnipiw dna ,hguoht ,deddon ehS
.delahxe eh sa seye sih desolc
siht otni reh ecrof ot gniog ton m’I esuaceB“
,dekrims nosillA ,ereh dnA
,rehtie noitpoda rof pu mih gnittup elbatrofmoc leef t’nod I dnA“
tnemyap fo dnik emos ylbaborP
yrtsap eht tsuj dah kciredoR .thgin taht
.denepo rotaregirfer eht dellup dna
,ffo deretnuas meht fo owt ehT  2 fo
”.taht htiw etib ll’I ,thgirlA“
taht rof emit fo ytnelp evah dluow ti dna
.ylprahs delahni ehS
,dnats thgin eht no detnuom enohp eht ot kcab denrut ehS
”.dooG“ .deddon kciredoR
.evom ton dluoc eh ,dehctah yllautca dah ybab eht taht won tub ,gnihctah gge eht tuoba deticxe neeb dah eH
.guh a ni degagne ylimaf elohw eht
.worg mih ees ot dehsiw llits reh fo trap a ,dlrowrednu lanimirc eht fo tuo saw eh taht won
,yltfos derepsihw nosillA
”,yltnecer gge na dial …ehS“
,yart eht debbarg eh os dna
”,ti htiw tuo ,thgirlA“
seye s’kciredoR .sehciwdnas tnassiorc s’yad txen eht rof hguod eht gniraperp tsuj saw kciredoR dna lasraeher htiw enod neeb dah nosillA retfa
dluoW .ybab elidocorc a eldnah ot woh aedi on dah ylbaborp ehs dezilaer kciredoR ,dnim ot emac ehs sA
,kcezzoW rreH yb
,kciredoR ta delims nosillA ”!haeY“
.ytic eht fo elddim eht ni letom hcaor a fo tuo detcepxe saw tahw saw taht niaga neht tub
,siht no reh liaf ton dluoc eH
,ni mih ekat ot deerga htob ev’ew dnA“ .dias eh
.ti raeh ton did tsomla kciredoR taht hguone tsuj
.ylimaf llams eno gnimrof
”,dlrow eht ni elitper tseb eht deirram I“
:retaeh ecaps eht ot txen dnuorg eht no gniyal saw taht rof nosaer ehT
,tsael ta swen doog saw htiw nigeb ot ti gniredisnoc saw kciredoR tcaf ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,moor rekcol eht ot klaw trohs a saw tI
.gnihtyreve dna eerup odacova deneteews dna
.dekool ti gnitivni erom hcum woh gnizilaer dna
”?serutcip ni neve toN“ .skeehc reh nwod dellips sraet eht fo tsrif eht sa seye reh gnisolc
,htaerb peed a koot aterG ”?…aterG“
.cisum secudorp osla eh erehw ,noertaP sih no erom neve dnif nac uoY
,dlihc eht htiw od ot gnihtyna evah ot desufer evah dluow eh ytilibissop eht saw ereht tlef syawla dah ehS .kciredoR htiw noitasrevnoc reh retfa gnicar saw dnim reh
.reihtaerb tib tsethgils eht tsuj eciov sih
.tuons sih no ssik eltneg a gnivael ,pu doots ehS
,tuo saw ehs ,mih no pu tperc dah ehs sa tsaf sA
”!mM“ .daehrevo gnimool mrots gnimoc eht tlef kciredoR ,etib a gnikat nopu delims nosillA sa dna
,delahxe aterG ”?gniod uoy
.stnerap sih morf htuoy sih fo sotohp ynam ni ti nees dah eh deedni dna
.niaga noops reh pu dekcip dna nwod kcab tas ehs sa daeh reh koohs nosillA
,dlrow eht htiw ecaep ta os tlef eh emit tsal eht rebmemer ton dluoc kciredoR
,deksa dah aterG nehw thgir siht deppord ti taht dah dlrow eht romuh fo esnes fo dnik tahw derednow eH
:revocrednu ereht saw ehs gniredisnoc
.dias ehs ”,emit ruoy ekaT“
.kcohs ni kcab gninael ,nethgit taorht reh tlef aterG
,drawrof denael eh ,did eh nehW
,warts saw ,revewoh ,fo lluf saw ti tahW
,kciredoR dias ”,wonk I“
.elbissop saw thguoht kciredoR neve naht erom denediw seye s’kciredoR ”?yllaeR“
.aterG ot kcab noitnetta sih gninrut erofeb ,ti ta dekool eH
.dias ehs ”,sseug I ,sey-
mih ot emac ehs tcaf eht tub ,saw yllareneg eh retsis sih morf degnartse woh wenk eh ,lla fo tsoM
.dnim ni taht htiw ytiC kroY weN ot yaw reh ekam ot elbmag eguh a saw ti dna
,ti tuoba thguoht eh
.niaga gge eht ta gnikool ,deknilb ehS
tsaor hsilgnE lluf eht htiw denibmoc ,tahT
,deknilb kciredoR
.gnihtyreve dna mih rof dehcaer taht sbmil elttil esoht htiw ,smra sih ni thgil os dna etaciled os tlef yug elttil ehT
.dedne llac eht ,siht htiW ”.esruoc fO“
.sredluohs daorb sih no sdnah reh gnicalp yletaciled dna
.rood rotaregirfer eht otni tsrif-daeh tuons sih fo pit eht dehsams tsomla kciredoR
neht dna ,syad eerht rof ereh eb ll’I
”?thgir ,mih rof eman a fo thguoht ev’uoY“
mih ees t’nac uoY“ ”?si taht dnA“
yb hguohtla ,yawa gnitlem detrats seirrow siH
.deilper kciredoR
”.wonk uoy ,ytefas sih rof si sihT“ .deilper kciredoR
.mih esiar ot tnaw t’nseod ehS“
”,ees I“ .yawa gnillup
”.etapicitna neve t’nod uoy syaw ni ti gnivorp peek uoy kniht I yltsenoh dna ,uoy ot erutan gnivigrof
”?hguoht ,taht yb detlusni eb yllaer ehs dluoW“
”?gnikniht uoy era eno hcihW
kniht I .rehtaf ruo retfA“ .deilper eh
”?dlihc nailitper a fo gnirats eht dnim t’nod uoy dnA“
rotaregirfer eht otni
.deksa eh ”?yllaer ,tahw-W“
,tsrif ta thguoht I tahw s’tahT“ .dias ehs
.seye sih denepo ybab elttil eht nehw saw taht dnA
.seitirohtua yb dellik tog tsomla
gnitfihs ylbisiv sredluohs sih ,delahxe eH
?erac ot ysub oot eb eh dluoW ?yawyna gnillac emoc retsis sih dluoW ?yob elttil eht ot doog eb eh dluoW ?rehtaf a gnieb eldnah eh dluow woh
:reh ot emoc ssendas fo gnap a tlef ehs
.keehc s’nosillA gnikcil yltneg
”,rebmun lausu ruoy t’nsi sihT“
,ylprahs delahni aterG
”.flesym nosrep retsooR deR a fo erom eb d’I gnikniht saw I“
drawrof erom elttil a sbmil elttil sih gnidnetxe ,siht ta delaeuqs eH
”?boj a rof resiaK eht ot kcab og d’I kniht uoy od yhw ,aterG“
neeb evah sgniht ,yletaL“
.emit tsrif eht rof thgil was eh sa ylthgils detcartnoc yeht dna
.gab leffud eht ot kcab gniklaw ,deddon ehS .dias ehs
.yltnetni gge eht ta dekool ehs
eh dna ,mraf a llif ot warts hguone
,elpoep lareves llac ot evah dluow yeht wenk eh ,dnim sih fo kcab eht ni
”?rehtaf doog a ekam d’I kniht uoy oD“
yletulosba nosillA gnidnif
----**---- ”.yademos uoy ees ll’I“ .dias ehs
ydob sih morf enog noisnet lla ,deddon kciredoR
”,sacuL fo gnikniht saw I“
?nosillA fo tahw dnA
.emulov lausu sti ta gniniamer eciov sih ,deilper kciredoR ”,ytilibisnopser fo level
.ni knis thguoht siht tel ot sdnoces erom wef a koot ehS .dias ehs ”,yakO“
”,ti tuoba uoy ksa ot gninaem neeb d’I ,haeY“
.dias ehs ”,kciredoR ,esaelP“
.saw niats eeffoc a erehw evoba tsuj ti no nettirw
”?xim eht otni dik erom eno s’tahW“ .dias ehs
”,epoh I ,efil dlo ruoy otni kcab uoy llup ot toN“
.deddon kciredoR .deksa ehs
,naicisum dna retirw a si ohw
.gge eht ot kcab gninrut ezag sih ,siht ta desuap kciredoR ”.esaelP
.edis eht ot decnalg kciredoR ”…ebyaM“
.drawrof gninael dna pu ti gnikcip
.mih ot txen nwod gnittis dna sredluohs sih ffo sdnah reh gnillup
.rebmun s’letoh eht s’tI“ .dias ehs
.ti fo tuo tekcoP toH a gnikam ylirassecen ton saw eh fi neve
.htuom eht ni drah oot ti kool ot tuoba ton saw eh dna
”?skniht ehs tahw rettam ti seod yhW“
”.mih ot taht od t’nac I“ .delahxe ehS
”…ybab ym s’ti …tsuj s’tI“
”,haeY“ ”?ni mih gnikat
.mih dnuora derettacs sthguoht dnasuoht a htiw kciredoR gnivael
,eldnah ot tol a si elidocorc gnuoy a enoyna naht retteb wonk uoY“
,delkraps taht munitalp ro dlog fo stogni on erew ereht ,thgil
,tsenrae ni tressed eht otni gud yllanif oot eh ,siht htiW .dias eh
.pot eht ta thgir demrof kcarc a ,dnoces a retfa ,neht dnA
”,leahciM saw eman siH“
:deknilb kciredoR
”,yletulosba hO“ .deksa eh
”?yug gib ,dnim ruoy no s’tahW“ .dias ehs
”.noitidnoc eno no
,skcart reh revoc ot dah ehs
,seiceps tnereffid fo stnerap owt htiw detacilpmoc erom
gge eht ot derutseg neht ehS
.reh ta gnikool ,ni dehtaerb eh ,llitS
”.ekas ruoy rof sgniht yas tsuj t’nod I won yb wonk dluohs uoy ,notsnarC kciredoR“ .ylderutan-doog delkcuhc nosillA .deksa kciredoR
”ograC suoicerP“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.detnemmoc nosillA
.ti edam d’eh elihw nehctik sih ni rekooc erusserp a neeb dah ti dna
,delims yllanif kciredoR
”.emas eht enod ev’dluow aterG
eh dna ,derugif eh ,ti od dluow elahxe tsal tahT
krab tunlezah-etalocohc htiw etelpmoc
:thgil eht ni gnivomnu deniamer taht eno
,thgin taht yllufsseccus eniacoc emos dereviled d’eW“ .deilper aterG
.gge eht sdrawot denael nosillA ”!si ti ereht ,hO“
.delahxe eh ,etunim a tuoba retfa dnA
”?dik ,uoy t’now ,yug gib siht ekil ll’uoy kniht I“ .gnilims
taht gniusrup htrow saw ti kniht ton did ehs tub ,ssalc-hgih erom hcum demia yllausu setsat s’aterG
,seye sih desolc kciredoR
,gnar enohp eht sa dnA
.did eh erofeb ti tuoba thguoht evah dluow ehs esruoc fo
.ylsuovren gnilahxe ,denrut neht ehS .dias ehs
.ssendoog nailatI yrettub fo reyal rehtona
”,tniop gnillepmoc a pu gnirb od uoy sseug I“
,sega ni dlihc a htiw tlaed ton dah eH
,taht tuoba duorp eb dluow erialC derugif eH
tooB dna pihW fo rohtua
:ecno ta daeh sih hguorht nar gnihtyreve ylnedduS
”.tib elttil a rof doog eb dluohs I
dah tI .yltnassecni etiuq ot kcab emoc dluoc yeht taht trofmoc a saw ti dna
.traeh sih ni ecalp ekat tliug fo gnap llams a tlef eh
elbbow gge eht was eh nehw
edisni spmal eht fo wolg thgil eht
.dettimda eh ”,t’ndluow ehs ,oN“
.ti gnizeeuqs dna dnah sih rof gnihcaer ,nosillA dias
.mih ot gninrut erofeb ,desuap neht ehS
.rehtegot emac gnihtyreve ,ecalp ni ti dleh taht warts eht ta neht dna dap gnitaeh eht ta kcab dekool eh sa dnA
.gniylpmi saw aterG tahw ta gnineffits sbmil sih ,deknilb kciredoR
.yltneg gniddon
.gnilahxe ,gge eht ta nwod dekool eH
”.mih fo erac ekat ot em deksa ehs oS
ton dluoc eh ot detnaw eh fi neve dna ,wonk ton did kciredoR
,og ot erehw wonk uoY“
2 traP ,kcezzoW rreH yb
.ria eht ot desopxe llits saw taht gge eht ta nwod gnikool ,delahni aterG
”.doR ,siht no tnemgduj ruoy tsurt t’ndid ehs fi uoy ot emoc dluow retsis ruoy kniht t’nod I ?ton yhW“
:dluoc yeht sa emoh ta emit hcum sa dneps ot tniop a ti edam dah yeht ,suhT .emit yna
”.sdrawretfa retsis ruoy llac ll’eW“
,deredisnoc ylsuoires reve dah eh gnihtemos ton saw doohrehtaF
.elbat eht fo dne etisoppo eht ot kcab gniklaw ,pu doots ehS .nosillA dias
,dnoces a koot ehS
,attoc annap klim laerec s’isoT anitsirhC etacilper ot emit tcefrep a eb dluow taht dediced d’eh ,suhT
”…s’eH .eno siht rof taht tnaw t’nod I .drah
.aterG ta pu gnikool ,deddon kciredoR .gab eht ni
…ti ees ot neeb evah dluow ti lufrednow woH
,yrtsap ffup eht ni noitanimal rehtona saw erehT
.relevart wollef ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,)2 fo 2 trap( kcezzoW rreH yb ”ograC suoicerP“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.dlrow eht ni ytic tseisub eht ni ekil kool dluow taht tahw
.dias ehs ”,eb nac I sa doog sA“
erom ehT .ecnahc a dik eht evig ot neeb dah ti ysae woh tuoba gnikniht
,nosrep ni yadhtrib tsrif sih ees ot ekil neeb evah dluow ti tahw ylfeirb derednow ehS
.deksa ehs ”?niaga reH“
:ti no eye na peek dluoc yeht os
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gniprihc erom tuo tel ybab elttil ehT
aterG yb detisiv tog I“
.erew seye reh der woh ees dluoc kciredoR ,thgil eht nI
.tuoba gnivom llits sbmil sih dna desolc llits seye
.rotabucni eht ni
.tsif a otni dehcnelc sdnah sih sa neffits liat sih tlef eH
”.tupni reh tuohtiw neve ,ti tuoba kniht ot emit deen ll’I …tsuJ“
dluohs ew em sdnimer taht sseug I“
.gge eht ta no dekool eh sa dnoces a tsuj rof gninediw seye sih ,desuap eH
.tae ot attoc annap klim laerec siht tog ev’ew ,tsrif tuB“
.ti tuoba deirrow llits ehs tub
.llew sa saw ti suoicerp woh tub ,saw ti etaciled woH
,yad eht ni retal ylevitaler saw ti
.gab leffud eht ta nwod gnikool ,delahxe ehs ,suhT
?siht won dna ,kaets eht neht ,retrats pollacs
”,od I ,haeY“ ”?epoh I
…ycnega noitpoda lautca na revo
.nwod dekool eh dna
”.esimorp a s’tahT .teem owt uoy tel ot yppah naht erom eb lliw I ,efil siht fo tuo teg nac uoy fi tuB“
,kroY weN ni srekab rehto ot derapmoc gnieb rof hcum ton saw eh
”,gnihton rof eb dluow siht lla neht dna
,ybab nailidocorc elttil eht dnuora elbmurc ot gge eht fo tser eht rof regnol hcum ekat ton did tI
,ti hsur ot ton wenk eh tuB
”?yllaeR“ .deknilb nosillA
.niaga delbbow ti ,neht dnA
…ot dah eh ,neht tsuj sgniht gniees neeb evah ot dah eH
”…siht esarhp ot trats neve I od woh ,doG“
”…emit ruoy ekat tsuj ,thginot eb ot esle erehwyna evah t’nod eW“
,trofmoc llams on saw emit siht suoiciled tuo denrut yllautca eerup odacova eht taht tcaf eht nevE
eb dluow noitseuq eht derugif I tub ,rehtom a eb ot detnaw syawla ev’I“ .dias ehs