.dloraH ot ezag sih gninrut erofeb ,roolf eht ot decnalg neht eH .deilper esroh eht ”,ris ,semit elpuoc A“
U“ .kcohs ni kciredoR ta pu gnikool ,deknilb dlareG
,hctab wen a rof eugnirem eht detrats I wonk uoy tel ot ereh revo emac tsuJ“
,ffo wohs ot snalp on dah eh tub ,enoyreve morf skool teg dluow eh niatrec saw eH
”,smeti niatrec no pirg ruoy nekaew ot desoppus s’taews raeh I ,wonk uoY“
”?eizziL ,gniog strat eugnirem redneval nomel tog ew evaH“
”.gnol oot ekat ot ton yrt ll’I“
,delbmert mra reh yaw eht neht deciton eh ,did eh nehW
,won nwod gniteiuq saw tI
.kroY weN fo ytic eht otni dna enalp eht fo tuo gnitteg fo rettam eht saw ereht won
.kciredoR deksa ”?aterG“
.deilper notnA ”,epoN“
.deilper kciredoR ”,doog ,dooG“
.reh dedrager eh sa gninediw seye sih ,dnuorg eht dekcams liat s’doR
”—gnidaeh eb ll’I os ,lortnoc rednu ti tog ev’uoy wonk I“
.seirtsap no kcots gnikat saw eh sa
.tsillec edistuo na ot gnicruostuo ton saw lihP kroY weN eht ecno rof dna ,seires trecnoc eht ni txen saw taht wenk eh
.taht fo tuo teg ot gniyrt er’uoy ,si trap tnatropmi eht tuB“ .dias eh
.roolf eht ot gninrut ezag sih
:efil ni noitautis sih no gnitcelfer
”.yug gib ,oot uoy ot gninroM“
.ereht pu morf gnivom ytic elohw eht ees dluoc yeht saw tnemtrapa s’nosillA dna sih pu hgih woh morf neve dna
.deilper kciredoR ”,uoy raeh I ,haeY“
.taht ta pecib sih otno sregnif erom owt decalp kciredoR
.tahwemos tcirtsnoc ot selcsum reh desuac taht yaw a ni ,dloc elttil a nur doolb reh edam thguoht ehT
.lla retfa ,ereht tuo tnatsnoc deyats ngis detnaw pleh eht yhw saw taht
.ylfeirb ecnartne eht rednu daeh sih gnikcud ,myg eht fo srood elbuod eht hguorht deklaw eh sa delahni kciredoR ,suhT
I“ .no dekool eh sa drah gniwollaws dlareG ,no dekool kciredoR .enam sih tsniaga drah denettalf srae sih yaw eht dna desnet smra sih yaw eht was
,emit a ta spuorg elcsum sih lla rof myg eht ni yllausu saw kciredoR
feiler ni dehgis ehS
,deddon dlareG ”…haeY“
.eit dna tekcaj kcalb-lla
,flesreh deleets
:saw ehs ereht ,deednI
:sorhtna detroppus taht myg tseraen eht ot teg ot kert a fo tib elttil a saw tI
,tey gniddehs detrats t’nevah selacs ym ,em rof ykcuL“
gnilgnij lleb eht ,nepo yrekab eht ot rood eht draeh eH .deilper kciredoR ”,raeh ot dooG“ ”!ereh dnuora eb nac sa htooms gnivom era sgnihT“
.siht ta delims kciredoR ”!esimorp I
.notnA ta dekool eh sa gniggurhs ,yawa dellup eH .deilper kciredoR
”!worromot uoy ees ll’I .emit myg s’ti ,em rof erots eht dnim ,yawynA“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.gninrom siht yrekab eht no ni dekcehc I nehw gnihtemos htiw laed ot dah I ,taht tuoba yrroS“
.denediw seye s’dlareG ,siht ta dnA ”.drocer lanimirC“
,no feiht yttep a ekat ot tib a decnivnoc eb ot dedeen dloraH“
.kcab tog eh emit eht yb emoh ta gnitiaw nosillA htiw ton
”.ti gnicudorp peek tsuj uoY“ .deilper eh
.siht ta delims kciredoR
.dehtacsnu devivrus ograc sti was ehs sa noos sa
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.emit gnol a rof ereht ni yats ot dednet eh ,syad myg no ,lla retfa
,setunim net tuoba retfA
,tuo smra sih ekahs ot
,llew os gniod saw ti ees ot tuons s’elidocorc eht ot elims a thguorb tI
”…llew ,secnahc dnoces tog reve ydobon fi ,sediseb dnA“
,nwod rehtruf dehcoocs neht tar ehT
no derutaef ti dah neve d’eh dna
.regnif sih no gnir yek eht gnilriwt ,deilper kciredoR ”!desirprus eb d’uoY“
,ytic eht fo trap siht ni kcehc dluoc ehs smyg erom owt ylno erew ereht tnaem tahT
.enihcam eht morf yawa dellup eh erofeb
.kcab eht sdrawot tuo denael dloraH ”.thgiR“
.slautir yliad sih rof tuo daeh ot emit saw ti dediced dah kciredoR ,enod siht htiW
drawrof gniklaw erofeb
”!desirprus yrev eb d’uoY“
.dlareG dias ”,haeY“
.dnah s’kciredoR gnikahs yllacitsaisuhtne
stnemevom s’dloraH taht llet dluoc kciredoR hguohtla ,eizziL ot kcab denrut dloraH ”.esruoc fO“
.noitanitsed txen reh ta nwod gnikool
yeh eht fo emos ffo dehsurb ehs sa gnilahxe ,siht retfa ecaf reh no sessalgnus reh detsujda ehS
noos sA .mra tfel sih no pmub thgils a tlef eH
.etarepsed erom elttil a gnidnuos eciov reh ,dias ehs ”,esaelP“
,ollec reh ot denrut neht nosillA ”!od uoy wonk I“
.dloraH ot dekool eh erofeb sremotsuc eht ot gninrut ylkciuq seye sih
.dias notnA ”,tib a tsuj ,haeY“
”!etal er’uoY !era ay ereht ,doR“ .rof ffo wohs dluow
,desuap notnA ,neht dnA ”—taht kniht uoY“
”.gninrom eht ni etal fo dnik s’ti ,deb fo tuo emoC“
.rehtorb reh ot kaeps ot dah ehs tub ,dnif ot snoitanitsed elpitlum fo eno dah ehS
.netsil tsael ta dluow eh eveileb ot dah ehs
”ograC suoicerP“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.drah yllaer gniyrt m’I“
”.hguone riaf ,hguone riaF“
gab leffud eht dleh ehs yaw eht dna
:yrruh on ni saw kciredoR tub ,elihw a koot llits tI
,nrecnoc ruoy dnatsrednu I“ .deddon kciredoR
.elidocorc eht ta decnalg eH ”…hu ,yllautcA“
.tuo yaw sih gnikam ,rood eht sdrawot denrut eh ,siht htiW
.dloraH ot kcab gninrut ,deddon kciredoR
----**---- .tuokrow eht fo ruoh tsrif eht rof pu elttob sih llif ot
.reve naht reireehc neve demees eh tuo htob erew yeht taht won dna
.nwo sti otni gnimoc yllaer saw ti dna
.wonk uoy ,od ot tol a evah yllaer t’nod I
.gninnirg ,revo dekool eh
.tnemhsilbatse enif a saw ti won
,ot desu ylluf reven saw eh noitasnes a saw ti
.kaerc duol eht pleh ton dluoc eh gib os saw kciredoR ,saw deb eht gib woh etipsed neve :revewoh
.edivorp t’ndluoc dnalsi eht taht syaw ni ynam
,kcab mih gnillup
.rood eht ot denrut eh ,siht htiw dna ,deddon kciredoR
.gniraeppasid tsaf yletinifed saw
.tcapmi eht morf ylthgils kcab gnillup redluohs tfel sih
,gninrub ydaerla erew sgel siH
”?ereh devil I wonk uoy did woH
.htaeneb tuoba gnittilf strap gnivom sti fo lla htiw
.ylthgils gnipoord srae sih ,dehgis dloraH
,ograc reh gniees tuoba elitsoh siht neeb dah renwo siht fI
,mih ees ot teg neve ton thgim ehS
.yad lluf a eb dluow ti wenk kciredoR taht hguone
”!nwod syug uoy tel t’now I
.tuohtiw od ton dluoc kciredoR taht pihsrentrap a saw ti dna
.deddon dloraH ,dnoces a retfA
”!doR ,ereht deeps yna pu kcip nac uoy desirprus m’I ,smra esoht htiW“
:tfel sih no yrarbiL cilbuP kroY weN eht fo hcnarb niam eht dessap eh
.deb ni pu gnittis ,denrut eh ,tnurg a htiW .deddon kciredoR
”?rof egrahc eht saw tahW“
…won gnorw og ot erew sgniht fI
”.gnihtyna em llet ot evah t’nod uoy
,shtaerb peed koot ehs ,suhT
”.won elihw a rof doog m’I os
”!setunim evif ylno eb ll’I“ .delkcuhc eH
.tnemtrapa esuohtnep rieht fo wodniw eht tuo gnikool ,denrut neht eH
,worromot ni emoC“ .delims kciredoR ”.wonk
”.taht fo sutats eht no ni kcehc ot detnaw tsuj I ,noitacilppa na dettimbus ydaerla yllacinhcet ev’I ,yllautcA“
”?taht eldnah neve sussim eht seod woH
.retnuoc eht no ssalg eht fo pot no dnah a decalp eH
”?setadpu tnatropmi rehto ynA“
”.won rof sremotsuc morf yawa siht llup dluohs ew ebyaM“
,myg txen reh ot klaw gnol eht nageb ehs ,suhT
.deniart saw ezag s’notnA erehw sdrawot kcab gninrut
.rood eht ot gninrut erofeb ,delims kciredoR ”.dooG“
”,eiteews ,lla ta toN“
…s’tI“ .dlareG dias ”,ris ,seY“
.fo elbapac saw elidocorc llat toof neves a sa yldnik sa dlareG ta nwod gnikool ,smra sih dessorcnu eH .deddon kciredoR
?ekil eb dluow myg lautca s’kciredoR fo renwo eht tahw wenk ohw neht
dna notnA ot txen enihcam pu llup eht ot gniklaw yllanoitnetni ,revo dessorc eh sa
”?gninrom siht hciwdnas gge evissam taht gnikam ot ti peek ot gniog tsuJ“ .dias ehs ”,dooG“
.etag eht otni dellup enalp eht sa
”—otni em depor sdneirf tsuJ .yrots gnol a
eh dna ,esnopser ni deneffits liat s’dloraH
,saw ytic eht tnarbiv woh tsuj mih kcurts syawla tI
.dloraH dias ”,yllaer toN“
.ylluferac elsia eht otni tuo ti gnillup erofeb ,delahxe ehS
suht ehS .raey a tsomla ni nekops ton dah yeht fi neve
.tnemtrapmoc daehrevo eht denepo ylkciuq ehs dna ,siht was ehs sa noos sa taes elsia eht fo tuo depmuj tsomla ehS
”.yadot myg eht rof ffo eb dluow uoy thguoht I !gninrom siht niaga uoy ees ot dooG“
:thgilf eritne eht fo kniht ot elba neeb dah ehs gniht ylno eht saw ereht pu gab leffud ehT
no elims daorb a htiw onihr evissam a doots ereht dna ,thgir sih ot denrut kciredoR
,dlrowrednu lanimirc eht ni esolc eb ot drah saw ti
.wot ni gab leffud a htiw ,nosrep ni saw ehs ereht won dnA
.elbisiv saw taht raet elgnis eht was ehs ,sessalgnus eht rednu tsuj dnA
,edistuo kool ot dnoces a koot kciredoR
”,yllA ,erom emos yalp uoy raeh ot detnaw I“ .dehgis kciredoR
”,thgirla s’ti ,hO“ .delims kciredoR
.elidocorc egral eht ta gniknilb
,yawa edir trohs a ylno saw nylkoorB taht ykcul saw eH
.gab leffud reh ot nwod dekool ehS
.pecib sih tsniaga regnif elgnis a gnippat ,deddon kciredoR ”.esle gnihtoN“
,ereht uoy pots ot gniog m’I“
,deredisnoc sgniht lla
”.ecnahc rehtona dik eht evig
”.ereh tuo ti od ot gniog ton er’ew dna ,od ot gnimmyg fo htrow s’yad eritne na tog ev’I ?detrats teg ew llahs ,yawynA“
.kcen s’nosillA fo edis eht pu gnikcil yltneg
fo drocer a evah uoy syas tI“ .deilper dloraH
.pu flesmih gnillup
.deilper kciredoR ”,lla ta ton ,hO“
,worb s’onihr eht ffo gniruop saw taews
.specirt sih ni nrub eht leef ot gninnigeb neht ylno saw kciredoR dna ,ni sruoh eerht tuobA
O“ .moor elohw eht pu nethgirb ot demees elims s’dlareG dna ,llef yletaidemmi sredluohs s’dlareG .dias eh ”,sepor
,ereht pu gninepo erew sessenisub wen deirav fo stol tnaem ti
leffud eht htiw tuo reh gniwehc melborp on dah myg eht fo renwo namuh dnuobelcsum rehtar eht :dud a saw tI
.deilper kwah eht ”,puY“ .deksa eh
S“ .redluohs sih ot pu dnah a thguorb eh kcab dellup eh
”?thgin tsal kcor taht no KO tpels uoY“
.kciredoR ot dekool eh sa srepap emos pu gnillup ,delahxe neht eH ”.si ti ereht ,thgir hO“
.niaga aterG revo dekool dna
,krow fo enil dlo sih ni tem dah doR ydobemos rof
”ograC suoicerP“ fo
.moor rekcol eht otni detaerter eh erofeb ,kniw a notnA dehsalf kciredoR
,yltneg delahxe ehS
.namow llams a fo etteuohlis eht yb
.nworc delacs sih no kciredoR gnissik dna
:sraey eht revo tnempoleved fo tol a gniees neeb dah aera eht taht dna
.nwod gnikool ,siht ta dennirg doR
myg eht ot nialpxe ot evah t’nod I tub ,eruS“
,knirhs ot nageb slipup sih woh
.eireganeM oirT fo rebmem a dna tooB dna pihW fo rohtua ,naicisum dna retirw a si ohw
.seye sih ni gnillew sraet eht ,daeh sih koohs eH
.dnah s’dloraH ni krowrepap eht ta dekool dloraH sa nwod gnikool meht fo owt eht ,tius dewollof dlareG dna kciredoR .tuo mih gnipleh dna enil eht fo tnorf eht ta elona eht ot gniddon yletaidemmi kwah eht
.deilper kciredoR ”,dloraH ,no dloH“
noitats orteM tseraen eht ot
,sraluger sih fo wef a deciton eh tub ,ti ta deklab evah yllamron dluow tsoM
.ykahs rehtar htaerb reh ,ni dehtaerb aterG
per sih hguorht yawdim
”.dab ,uoy ot klat ot deen I
”.ereh sneppah ti nehw lluf ylneddus era snib hsart rieht yhw srenwo
.doR ta pu gnilworg ,nwod enihcam eht tel ylwols notnA
.ega sih nam a rof erew yllausu yeht sa ylevil sa ton erew
”.yson gnieb m’I fi yrroS“
,llat ytterp doots llits eh tuB
,siht ta delims kciredoR ”!lla ta ton ,hO“
”?trats uoy nac nehW“
lufreehc etiuq dekool syawla noxaM notnA :ecaf sih ot elims a thguorb thgis ehT .ecaf sih
”,raeb ot sessorc ruo tog lla ev’eW“
.tuo em raeh ,doR ,esaelP“
.ylkciuq ti od ot dah ehs dna
”.drah oot sserts t’nod ,enif er’uoY“ .dias eh
.gnidliub txen eht sdrawot yrekab eht fo tuo gniog enil a ees ot elba saw eH
.ffo saw ngis eht ees ot feiler taerg ni pu dekool ehs dna
,siht retfa ylduol rehtar kaerc did deb ehT
,smret elbacima tsael ta no evael ot hguone secarg doog s’resiaK eht otni nettog dah kciredoR .srennur sih fo eno neeb dah aterG sa gnol sa ylraen
ees dluoc kciredoR seye s’esroh eht fo elkraps eht ni dna
.deilper esroh eht ”,ris ,seY“
”.no ti tup uoy nehw emit siht ti hcrot ot tegrof t’noD“ .deilper dloraH
,oN .delahxe ehS
.onihr eht ta nwod dekool eh sa
”,boj a detnaw ohw dik emos tsuj ,on ,hO“
.aterG gnidrager ,desuap doR
.tisiv ylimaf a rof ecalp dna emit ddO“
”?siht rof hguone tnatropmi eb ylbissop dluoc tahW“
”.erots eht otni feiht yttep a gnittel ,epols yreppils a fo tib a s’tI“ .deilper eh
”?riS“ .deplug dlareG
----**---- .tuo ytpme ot enalp eht rof detiaw ehs sa flesreh gnimlac
,eneg notsnarC taht ot sknaht saw eh sa gib sa ylraen saw aterG
”?ecalp siht fo renwo eht uoy erA“
”?ereh gnineppah s’taht kniht uoY“
.dworc eht fo eltsub eht revo gnitcejorp llits hgual enillatsyrc ,teiuq sih ,dehgual dloraH
”.ti gniod er’uoy elihw ni klaw I fi gniyalp ruoy brutsid ll’I diarfa syawla m’I“ .dias eh
.ffo saw gnihtemos wenk kciredoR siht was eh sa noos sA
.ot pu nekow evah ylbissop dluoc eh gniht tseb eht saw ti ,gnihtyna fi
.noitisoporp reh ot stcaer eh woh dna
”,ni emoc uoy nehw worromot krowrepap eht fo erac ekat ll’eW“
”?ti saw ,dab gnihtyna t’nsaw tI“
rekcol eht sdrawot daeh sih htiw gnirutseg erofeb ,dehgis kciredoR ,yllaniF
.troffe eht morf gnitnurg ,pu flesmih dellup ylpmis doR .deksa eh
.ylduol rehtar
.tius sih fo tekcop tsaerb eht ni meht gnittup dna pu srepap eht gnidlof ,delahxe dloraH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dnah reh ni gab leffud eht gnidloh elbuort on dah ehs denigami eh os
t’nod ,neht yb ereht eb ll’I .ruoh na tuobA“
.dloraH ta nwod dekool eH
,relevart wollef ruoy
,delkcuhc notsnarC nosillA
.retteb netsil dluoc eh os edis sih no thgiew elbaredisnoc sih gnillor ,dehgis suht eH
:ni ti gnikat ,desuap eH
sboj neewteb emit eht ssap ot pu dekcip d’eh ybboh a thguoht reven d’eH
”.sruoh wef a ni strats hsur hcnul emit eht yb ydaer era erom erus gnikam kcab eht ni si ayidaN ,tuo
.ti htrow saw gninrom yreve mih ta pu dekool ehs yaw eht gniees tub
”?thgir ,drow a tuohtiw yb og sniart eht sekam gniht elttil enO“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.ylthgils roolf eht no gnikcalc snolat reh
,tsap evom esroh tfard a was eh ,nwod dekool eh sa
,)sdaerb sih fo eno ekam ot yppah naht erom neeb d’eh erehw(
.llaw eht tsniaga pu dekcab
.nwod gnikool ,dlareG sdrawot daeh sih dewob kciredoR .deksa eh
.retnuoc eht ot kcab denrut neht dna ,deddon dloraH
”?thgir ,yawyna noos eb lliw lasraeheR“
.citceh saw tbuod on ti erehw
,edisni no gniog saw tahw tsuj derednow eh hguohtla
semit owt ro eno retaE
.redluohs eht no notnA gnittap ,drawrof emac doR ”!notnA yeH“
,noertaP sih no erom neve dnif nac uoY
.erehwesle og ot dah eh tnaem
”.tsafkaerb nwo ruoy eraperp uoy elihw gnicitcarp ym dnim t’nod uoy epoH“ .riahc
,dednuos peeb gniynapmocca eht sa noos sa dehcnilf ehS
saw siht :htiw nigeb ot ereht ni saw tahw ees ot tnaw ton dluow eh taht ytilibissop eht ecaf ot dah osla ehS
,mih kootrevo tnemssarrabme fo evaw a
.ylpeed ni dehtaerb aterG
sti htiw ,tey pu evig ot ydaer neeb ton dah ehs wenk doR taht tius eht ni desserd saw ehS
lliw ydobon nehw drah s’tI
!ereht em ees ll’uoy neht ,thgirlA“
.gninworf ,noitamrofni eht rof retnuoc eht rednu dehcaer neht eH .deilper dloraH
.kciredoR ta kool ot pu gninrut seye sih ,desuap neht eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.daed pots dluow dlrow elohw eht kaerb a enoyna evag reve ydobon fi tub
.drawrof daeh sih dewob kciredoR
ti tub ,dnuora kcuts llits ruf nworb s’tar redlo ehT
,evitarcul os emoceb dluow
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffaruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”.taht ekil loot a eldnah ot redro ni eb ot evah d’ehS“ .deilper notnA ”,teb ll’I“ .doR dias
:myg detsurt tsom sih ,suhT
,)yllaer ,ssenetal rof drocer a( etal setunim enin tuoba neeb ylno dah eh fi neve :tsrif ni mih kcehc ot thguoht dah onihr eht lufknaht saw kciredoR ,tuo ffuts sih teg ot tnew eh sA
,htaerb peed a koot kciredoR
demarf ,deb eht ssorca yalps thgil eht was kciredoR
:pots gniyalp ollec eht draeh eh taht siht ta saw tI
.deilper nosillA ”,haeY“
,kcezzoW rreH yb
.reh fo tnorf ni tser taes eht tsniaga walc a gnippat
:rehto hcae htiw esolc ylralucitrap neeb reven dah enildoolb notsnarC eht fo srebmem ehT
”!gninrom siht stnassiorc revotfel ruoy fo eno ot flesym depleh I dnim t’nod uoy epoh I“
.ylkciuq daeh sih ot pu gnitaerter sredluohs sih dnuof eh dna
.ffo deklaw ehs erofeb dnah ta esolc ograc reh gnidloh
.yrekab sih ot tsomla saw eh taht langis sih saw taht
,myg eht edisni repeed rehto hcae tsniaga gnikcalc sthgiew fo sdnuos eht raeh dluoc eH
,ytic doof a saw kroY weN tub
smra siH .osrot sih no krow detrats dah eh neht tsuj ylno saw ti dna
.ylevitcetorp tsomla
.niatrec rof saw taht ,tsub a saw myg siht raelc saw tI
:rednow ot nageb ehs reh fo tnemtaert s’renwo myg eht retfa tub ,detnorfnoc tey ton dah ehs ytilibissop a
”,htiw revo s’ti dna ecno ffo semoc ti tsael tA“
resiaK eht rof recrofne na sa kcuts kciredoR htiw
yllufyalp dias eh
”,gninrom siht taht gniod dehsinif tsuJ“ .deksa eh
.dloraH ot gninrut ,deddon dlareG
:dnim ton did kciredoR tub
,pu dekool neht eH ”.sknahT“
ruf gniyerg eht was eh ,retnuoc eht ta ,suht dnA .ti debbud eh sa
.nwod draobpilc eht gnittup ,delims eh dna ,yletaidemmi tsomla dewohs hteet kcub owt siH
.hciwdnas sih dehsinif dah kciredoR retfa noos lasraeher rof tuo dedaeh dah nosillA
----**---- .hciwdnas tsafkaerb gninrom kramedart sih ekam ot esu dluow eh
.ecalp ni flesmih dleh eh sa gnitnurg
,lla retfa ,dniheb efil dlo sih tfel d’eH
”.ffuts od dna rekcol eht ot teg si od ot deen uoy lla ,ereh tog I nehw ni uoy gningis fo ytrebil eht kooT“ .kciredoR fo tnorf ni dnah dehctertstuo na morf yek a gnilgnad ,ksed tnorf eht sdrawot deddon neht eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sregnif sih fo tuo noisnet emos gnikahs saw eh taht gniciton kciredoR ,delahxe dlareG ”.dias eh ekil ,tfeht yttep ,hU“
”ograC suoicerP“   yojne esaelP
.enihcam pu-llup eht ot kcab gninrut erofeb ,denworf kciredoR ”.tnatropmi s’tI“
,sgniht esoht lla fo eton koot ylsuoires eh neht ylno saw tI .dereviuq waj reh yaw eht
,kciredoR fo tuo detnaw aterG tahw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .rellevart wollef
,noisserpxe s’esroh eht deton kciredoR
,egdirf sih ot gninrut erofeb ,deddon eH
.dnah sih pu dleh kciredoR esle gnihtyna yas dluoc eh erofeb tub ,htuom sih denepo dloraH
.krow fo enil reh ni bac a ksir ton dluoc ehs wenk aterG tub ,yawa syaw a fo tib a saw tI
”.gniht ruoy od uoY“
,deilper aterG ”,yrots gnoL“
.tnorf ni tuo thgir ,yrekab sih :saw ti ereht dna ,yrarbil cilbup eht dnuora renroc eht denrut eh ,yllaniF
.emitgib ffo diap ti dna
.niaga rood eht tuo deklaw nosillA
”?emit ruoy did uoy gnimussa m’I dnA“
”?sey ,sggiM dlareG …enO“
,esac yalpsid eht fo ssalg eht no yletaciled sdnah sih decalp eH .dias dlareG
.dias eh ”!ris ,yrros-
.gab leffud reh revo ecilop eht llac ot gninetaerht erofeb
,ylsuovren deplug eH ”…m’I“
”.ruoh siht ta ereht ni s’ydobon ,ereht ni klat s’teL“ .moor
dlos sah hctab tsriF
.seye neerg ediw htiw stnetnoc sti gninnacs ,gab leffud eht deppiznu yletaidemmi aterG
”?yug gib ,ereht revo gnitaewS“
:saw yllausu ti sa nrets sa ylraen ton saw noisserpxe reh taht deciton eh ,revo reh dekool eh sa noos sA
,gnidliub tnemtrapa eht detixe eh ,suhT
.meht revo dnah sih dessap eh sa tsuj pu gnikrep srae sih ,enam sih hguorht dnah a nar eH ”…hu-
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.moor txen eht ni ollec a fo enot tfos eht saw
.deddon esroh ehT
.kwah gnikool-regnuoy a ot denrut tar ehT
:hguoht ,edisni pleh ot seeyolpme erom erew ereht dehsiw ylno eH
,kraP tnayrB morf yawa gninrut erofeb sremotsuc eht fo emos ot deddon eh dna ,tfel eh sa mih dniheb demihc lleb ehT
.mih ot pu dekool ehs sa nosillA ta nwod gnikool ,ereht tas elidocorc eguh ehT
.kcolc eht ot dekool neht eH
.sruoh xis koot taht fo tsom dna
,god.ecioveht ta
.ereht ni orhtna fo seiteirav lla tif ylbanosaer dluoc taht ecalp ylno eht ylbaborp ,esuoheraw remrof a ni denepo dah taht myg a ot gnola gniog detrats d’eh
”,kciredoR ,siht tuoba wonk t’nod I“
.deggurhs eH .deksa notnA
retuaL dloraH fo
kroY weN fo lla :mih dezama syawla weiv ehT
”.emit no pu wohs ot erus eb tsuj ,won roF“
.enalp eht ni kcab tas ehs erehw enigne eht fo raor eht leef dluoc
”,moor eht hguorht gnipmots elidocorc evissam a naht sgniht esrow hguorht neeb sah nipdne ym ,uoy gnillet peek I dnA“
.erofeb no nekat reve dah ehs boj yna ekilnu raef a saw siht
,deggurhs eH .deilper doR
gnisuap osla doR
.moordeb eht fo tuo yaw sih edam eh sa gnikcud ,pu doots eH .dias eh
tnassiorc cificeps eht tuo gnikcip
.ylfeirb sgel sih gnihcterts ,revo tneb eH
.tib elttil a xaler
.emit yna od nac I“
.noitarepsaxe sih gnisserpxe eciov sih ,dias eh
”,tnemesab eht ni nwod ysaekaeps nwo ruoy trats rO“
”.won morf setunim evif tuoba ni og ot ydaer eb dluohS
erofeb sesu sti dah d’ti elihw dna
,drawrof denael eH
,meht htaenrednu tuoba delwarps
.llaw eht tsniaga gninael ,siht ta delkcuhc notnA
.ereht dial eh sa ylwols rehtar mih fo ffo gnimoc peels
detrats dna ti esaeler dluoc eh litnu pu rab tal eht detfil ylwols kciredoR sa dna
eh nosrep rehto eno ylno saw ereht ,esruoc fO
,thgiew eht derewol ylwols onihr ehT
,yrekab eht fo sweiver rallets draeh ydaerla d’eH
,yltneg flesmih tel eh ,saw ti sa
”…hrrrrG“ .deralg eh sa lruc rehtona hguorht yawdim ,delworg notnA .deksa kciredoR
”?ti dessecorp uoy evaH“
,emoh lufituaeb ,efiw lufituaeb
”.dlareG ,maet eht ot emocleW“
.esac yalpsid eht dettap neht eH
.dias dloraH ”!kciredoR“
”,thguoht fo niart taht nwod og ot tnaw neve t’nod I“
”,boj siht deen yllaer I ,esaelP“
,kcab eht ot tnew kwah ehT ”.esruoc fO“
.enil eht ni remotsuc a gnivif hgih neve dna tuo yaw sih gnippiks tsomla mih ees dluoc kciredoR dna ,erots eht detixe dlareG ,siht htiW
”.yadot eb d’I erehw wonk htob I dna uoY“
saw gnihton lla fo tsom tub
.tuo gnihsur emac ehs sa norpa reh gnitsujda ,tuo thgir delip kwah ehT ”!gnimoC“ ”?setunim fo elpuoc a rof esuoh fo tnorf eht eldnah uoy nac ,eizziL“
niatnuof retaw eht sdrawot gnivom dna lewot dna elttob retaw sih gnillup ,rekcol sih denepo eh ,suhT
.tekcaj tius kcalb reh morf
”,esle gnihtyreve seod ehs yaw eht ,sdnah ytniad htiW“
sa dna ,denediw seye eulb krad s’esroh ehT
----**---- .tops myg lausu sih ot dna
.deilper dloraH ”,uoy knahT“
.tnemhsilbatse eht fo fehc eht sa mih ezingocer ot demees t’nerew taht esoht dna
”,wonk d’uoy erus m’I ,hO“
.yruxul taht dah enoyreve ton wenk eh dna
,drawrof dehcaer dlareG ”!doG ym hO …hO-
.drager a hgih os etiuq ni aterG dloh ton did eh gnileef a dah eh tub
,sper owt rehtona did eH .deilper doR
taht dna ,nattahnaM no enon erew ereht
reh ta kcab gnittis dna edis sti no dial dah ti erehw morf pu ti gnikcip
”.ti gnileef t’nsaw I fi yadot ni emoc evah t’ndluoW“
.setunim net tuoba rof
:etoxiuQ noD eb ot dah ti
.redluohs reh revo gnicnalg
”.eiteews ,gninrom dooG“ .sdnah dewalc gib sih fo eno htiw drawrof gnihcaer ,delims eH
,rentrap tuo-krow tseb s’dlrow eht llits saw notnA :wenk eh tahw demrifnocer ylno ti
.dlareG dias ”,wonk I-
”?thgiR .uoy ni eveileb ot enoemos deen tsuj uoy taht ,si ti drah woh wonk I
epoh lla tsniaga gnipoh
----**---- .detneuqerf kciredoR eno eht saw ti taht
”?neppah ot erew taht fi ebuTuoY no snoitces stnemmoc eht enigami uoy naC“
strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
eht uoy wohs nac I dna ,neht eciffo eht ni eb ll’I
”?ris ,I ma ,esle gnihtyna deen ot gniog ton m’I“
”!lla retfa ,t’nod uoy fi tsaf dab og ll’sgniht esohT“
,kroY weN ot gnitteg retfa tsuj ecalp elttil eht thguob dah eH
rellihc tsalb eht ni gnilooc neeb sah druc eht dna
,eceip eno ni hguorht nettog dah ograc eht taht woN
”.ereht teg uoy woh wonk I ,t’now I“ ”.yrrow
.pot knat sih ta dellup kciredoR ”.ma I“
.esle enoyna ot og ot elbaulav oot saw ograc ehT
.mih ta delims ehs dna ,daeh sih revo dehsurb dnah etaciled reH .dias ehs
,dnekeew sih fo yad tsrif eht saw siht gniredisnoc ,ereht mih gniteerg ecaf tnereffid a eb dluow ereht taht ni gniog wenk eh ,revewoH
.enil eht tsap thgiarts gnivom ,pot knat sih no dellup eh ,suhT
.yart ytpme-flah a ta nep sih fo dne eht gnitniop
:tops eht no og tel ylraen yrev doR ”?aterG“
,gninepo ta thgir ereht em ees ll’uoY !uoy knahT“
,thgieh reh revo tsuj saw taht elidocorc llat a dnimreven ,eman taht yb nam a fo draeh reven dah eh denoitnem eh ,kciredoR tuoba noitseuq reh ot netsil ot hguone nwod demlac dah eh nehw dna ,gab
,ot dah eh :lla retfa ,doolb yb detaler erew yehT
.dias eh ”!kcul dooG“
”?ngis detnaw pleh eht nees ev’uoy gnimussa m’I“
”?tnaig ypeels uoy ,huh ,ekawa yllanif er’uoY“
,emoh ta yltnegilid erom pu mraw ot evah dluow ehs tnaem ti esruoc fO
.retne ot detpmetta dah ehs myg tsrif eht fo tuo deppets aterG
,ngis tleb taes eht ot pu denrut seye reh dna
”.tsrif sgniht emos mih ksa ot tnaw I“ .nwod dekool eH
”.ereh ton ,yas t’nac I“ .deksa eh
:denepo rood eht ,dnoces a retfA
2 fo 1 traP ,kcezzoW rreH yb
.edis eht no kciredoR gnigdun ,dekniw eH .deilper notnA
,yliraew deknilb eH
.pu retaw seye sih ees dluoc kciredoR dna
”,no uoy ekat t’nac ew yhw wonk uoy erus m’I nehT“
.moor rekcol eht otni detaerter eh sa kciredoR ta delims notnA
…dna ,sthgiew elbissop tsehgih eht ta neve tuo-krow eht fo ruoh tsrif eht tlef ylerab
.smra sih gnissorc ,deddon kciredoR ”.dik ,ma I deednI“
.niaga ti gnirewol erofeb ,niaga enihcam gnilruc eht no dellup notnA
.yek eht koot kciredoR ”!uoy knahT“
.erom gnihtyna rof deksa evah ton dluoc eh
”?sdehs syawla niks ruoy woh sa emas eht ti si ,onnud I“
pu gnikaw nopu draeh notsnarC kciredoR gniht tsrif ehT
”?wonk uoy ,uoy ekat
.enihcam eht no pu gnillup erofeb delahxe notnA ”.feiler a s’taht ,lleW“
aterG dna ,hcaorppa wols a saw tI
.tuhs ti depmalc tub ,gnihtemos yas ot waj sih denepo eH
”.dik a sa tfeht yttep
”?thgir ,won thgiarts og ot gniyrt er’uoy ,si tnatropmi s’tahW“
:retteb eht rof tuo denrut dah sgniht yas ylefas dluoc eh taht htiw dna
:enihcam gnilruc a ni dleh mra sih ,yawa raf oot ton saw notnA
taes eht fo edisrednu eht tsniaga dehsurb liat s’notsnarC aterG fo selacs ehT
”?rof si siht kniht uoy od tahW“
?gniht emas eht od yllaer eh dluow
:reh revo gnirewot deniamer kciredoR ,detaes nevE
”,neht tuo ti evah ll’uoy ,dooG“
”.neht ,ecnahc a mih evig ll’I“ .deddon eH
.tsehc nwo sih otni regnif a detniop eh sa dloraH sdrawot yldetniop daeh sih gniwob ,deggurhs eH
.ylthgils yrev dereviuq waj rewol reh yaw eht ees dluoc eh taht tsap neve tub ,ecaf reh no dleh erew sessalgnus eht
,kcezzoW rreH yb
.sdnah sih debbur neht eH
.dias eh ”,od I sseug I ,haeY“
.cisum secudorp osla eh erehw
”!lla retfa ,nosaer a rof stnassiorc dezis nwo ym ekam ot daH“ .delahxe eH ”.puY“
.htuos yaw sih edam eh sa dworc eht tsgnoma tuo gnidnats emarf ytfeh sih
…thguan rof eb dluow ereht teg ot enod dah ehs gnihtyreve dna
.llew yllaer ffo gnikat si tnassiorc elimomahc-etalocohc wen eht wonk ot yppah eb ll’uoy ,lleW“ .delahxe neht eH
,em ekat lliw esle ydoboN“
.yraunaJ ni deneppah tahw ekil ,wonk uoY“
”.ytic eht tuohguorht lla deirt ev’I