dleif a ni saw eH
”.gnuoy s’eH .wonk I“
.meht delzzun dna owt rehto eht dnuora smra sih depparw dna
.tcatni egalliv eht was eh sa traeh sih ni demossolb yoJ
”,yhtrow m’I“ .dekramnu enots sti
.erofeb desu dah flow detniap
”.tsrow eb lliw gnidoolf eht erehw ees ot ekil dluow I“ .deksa ehs
.ssarg eht ni gnihcaorppa enoemos fo eltsur eht draeh eh sa dekcilf srae sih nehT
”?hteet noil eseht erA“
”.tuo em dewollof ehs ,gniteem eht retfA“
.yruf sih htiw delttar ecalkcen sipal siH .detuohs rihaT ”!ton yletulosbA“  2 fo 2 traP
er’uoY“ .liat sih deggaw dna tpew ihcakA dna
”.si eh ohw swonk dna
.sroloc s’lakcaj remrof eht gnizingocer etipsed
ta noitamrofni erom etavacxE
”.gnisselb s’tirips a rof ylimaf sih secifircas ohw
mih ssik ylecreif ot
eht ot ekow ihcakA  .deraor rednuhT
,noosnoM ekovni ot nalp yksir a detcocnoc
.delley irokO ”!seY“
”,sruoy ma I sa trosnoc ym eb lliw eH“
”.yellav eht dnuora stsim eht esiar ot deerga seilil ehT .ti did eW“
.irokO gnitniap detrats amihC dna eh ,dehsinif erew sgnikram sih nehW .devirra noosnoM nehw yaw eht fo tuo yats tsael ta ro tcepser reporp wohs ot rebmemer dluow amihC depoh eH .ti rednu niarts eht raeh dluoc eh tub ,laivoj tsomla saw enot s’rehtorb siH .deleviws rae s’ihcakA ”.retal
.gninommus deliaf a fo secneuqesnoc elbissop eht deyalpnwod eH
.kniht uoy naht eroM“
.mih ediseb gnidnats irokO ot sa flesmih ot hcum sa
.thgir sih ot duorp dna llat doots asem der ehT
.etulf sih no sregnif sih decalp amihC ”.si tI“
.ylneve dias itiwA
.etsaw ot og ot taht rof etah d’I dna tniap raw edam ydaerla I ,sediseB“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.detpmorp itiwA ”,eunitnoC“
.niar eltneg fo rettap tfos
.yellav eht fo tser eht eciton eh did neht ylnO
”?licnuoc eht ni em kcab uoy did yhw
”,od uoy kniht t’nod I“ ”.ees I“
.daor eht nwod gniklaw eunitnoc ot denrut itiwA .deggurhs ihcakA
.kcalb tsomla erew sduolc eht dna won redrah gnillaf saw niar ehT ”.siht od s’teL“
”?ydaeR“ .pu dekool
.repsihw a evoba ylerab saw eciov siH
.seye sih otni llef spordniar nehw gniknilb ylno
”.eciohc tsrif ym t’nsaw eH“
”,diarfa ton m’I .seY“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”,nem regnuoy eht htiw secnaillad ruoy fo swonk enoyrevE“ ”?hO“
”.sgnisselb rof desu si ikuH .gnireffo
.noinapmoc ruoy eb dluohs raeF .roirraw
,dehcuot dah revir eht erehwyrevE
.ihcakA ekil desserdnu
,dias ihcakA ”,raw ekam ot tuo gniog erofeb ti htiw sevlesruo tniap eW“
tseirp roirraw eht ihcakA
.daeh sih fo ekahs a htiw dias ihcakA ”,hsiw I“
.kcor dehsurc htiw dexim niser tnalp a s’tI“ .dias amihC
dnA“ .deretnuoc eh ”,era uoy seY“
”?ylreporp ti od ot tiaw t’ndluoc owt uoY“ .dehgis dna rehtorb sih ta dekool ihcakA ”.em depleh amihC“ .delims irokO .deksa ihcakA ”?ydaerlA“
dna denruter thgis sih sa depsag ihcakA  .selbmur tnatsid emoceb ot yawa deid rednuht eht neht dna kcarc a htiw derettahs dlrow ehT ”!ssel on evresed I ,yhtrow em dnif uoy fI“ .demaercs ihcakA
.eud ym nekat evah I elihw erahs rieht stnavres ruoy nevig evah I .eman ruoy ni seimene ym detnuh evah I
”.em stsurt ehS“ ”?dnA“
ebirt eht ni lakcaj elbatius a dnif ot nalp sih tuo dial ihcakA
egalliv ehT .sroirraw ynam fo eno si eh dna esolc era eW“
.seye s’lakcaj eht otni dekool eh nehT
llams tlef eH .mih dnuora delriws
.deggurhs eh nehT
.rewop yb deyaws era elpoeP“
mrots eht fo yruf lluf eht ees dluoc eh ,segamiretfa eht hguorhT
”?noitpo rehto ym s’tahW“
.moor ralucric eht fo retnec eht ni lwob ssarb eht ni gniwolg senots eht morf thgil der tniaf eht ylno saw erehT
ekamer uoy dnamed I ,dlrow siht edamer uoy sA“
.worb reh deworruf dna eson reh tuo deffuh itiwA ”.meht rof sesu ynam evah stseirp dna snamahs ruO
.sksir eht swonk eh erus ekam lliw I dna amihC“ .kcab dennip srae sih ,deerga ihcakA ”,wonk I“
”.denigami evah dluoc reve I naht lufituaeb erom
.ydob dehtolcnu sih revo dehsaw
.dniheb gniliart irokO htiw ynoclab eht sdrawot denrut dna htaerb peed a koot eH
,amihC was dna kool ot denrut eH
”.og dluoc ti dab woh reh dlot I“ .dehgis eH
,yks tsacrevo eht ta pu derats dna delims flow detniap ehT
.der suonimo ,thgirb a yks eht detniap dna esor nus eht
retsnom a ton ma I ,swalf ym gnikoolrevo elpoep rehto tuoba lliw uoy tahw yaS
.eb ot tnaem saw ti sa dlrow ehT
tsehc s’rehtorb sih no
irokO ot tuo top eht dleh amihC
.gnitniap dehsinif eh sa deddon ihcakA
,em fo evorppa t’nod uoy fI“
”seiliL fo tseirP“
”,yree yletinifeD“
”?rof desu ti s’tahW“
”?tnatropmi yllaer s’tahw taht t’nsI .efas si ylimaf ruO“
”.rewsna na fo hcum ton s’tahT“
.licnuoc egalliv eht edausrep tsum yeht tsrif tuB
”.mih fo ti ksa uoy esuaceb ylpmis ,ksa uoy gnihtyna od lliw dna gnuoy si eH“
”.lautir siht tuoba hturt eht em llet ot gniog er’uoy nehT
.sgel sih gnitniap detrats lakcaj eht sa elims a flesmih gniwolla
tnecs dercas ,teews eht delahni eh dna elzzum sih dehsurb sevael tew ,tfoS
.dekcilf liat s’flow detniap ehT
”.noitulos gnisimorp a yltcaxe toN“
”?tseirp s’yliL eht eb uoy lliW“
”.pup yrgnuh a ekil senihw ohw enoyna tcepser ot gniog t’nsi noosnoM
.sdniw eht ni eciov a raeh ot gnipoh
.ti dnamed dluohs ew ,scigam tsetaerg reh tnaw ew fi ,eromrehtruF
gnitniap erew yeht sA
yellav eht dnuora dekool ihcakA
erongi elpoep taht hcus si rewop ruoY
.ekat ot gniog era uoy nem ruo fo eno hcihw wonk ot tnaw I“
ti denrut dna daeh s’lakcaj eht debbarg eH
.thgim sih lla htiw delley eh
.t’nod srehto eht raef I tub siht ees I
dna stsim eht otni yarts ohw esoht ekat eW
dna sredle rehto eht yb detovtuo saw rihaT ,dne eht nI
.rae na dniheb dehctarcs ihcakA ”.saw I“
.eulb dercas rieht htiw derevoc saw yellav eritne eht ;demoolb seilil
.yellav eht ees t’ndluoc eH
ecneulfni ruoy desu uoy ,thginot dnA
ria eht ni yvaeh saw niar fo tnecs ehT
.eciov sih denetfos eH ”.eb dluohs uoy
.smra reh dessorc lakcaj ehT
”,gnisimorp skool rehtaeW“
.feiler fo hgis a dehtaerb ihcakA
.thgin eht otni peed deunitnoc stnemugra ehT
.ylbanosaer dias ehs
.noisiv sih derrulb sraeT
.ylper t’ndid ihcakA ”.su
.no welf ti erofeb tcepser ni daeh sti deppid tirips ehT
redrah llaf ot detrats niar ehT
”.yhtrow m’I“ .derepsihw eh
.elzzum s’irokO deson ihcakA ”.dooG“
”,trosnoc a sa nam a gnikat uoy fo evorppa lliw enoyreve ton ,eromrehtruf dnA“
”.mih esol ot droffa nac
.noitcejbo s’lakcaj tsedle eht detroppus esle eno oN
.rehtorb sih delzzun amihC ”.ton esruoc fO“
fo slautir rof doolb esu yltsom eW
.kcab dennip srae sih ees dluoc eno on depoh eH
.dlrow ruoy gnikamer ni trap ym enod ev’I ,niar yrevE
.htuos eht ot werg sduolc eulb krad ,yawa shtnom erew sniar eht hguoht nevE
.redluohs eht no irokO depmalc amihC ”.thgiR“
.kcalb dna egnaro fo sgnikram elbisivni ylraen sih morf tuo doots sgnikram etihw s’ihcakA
.kcab reh dniheb swap reh depsalc lakcaj eht ,meht raehrevo dluoc esle eno on nehW
saw enot s’lakcaj ehT
dluoc ohw egalliv eht ni wef eht fo eno osla saw ehs ,noitidda nI
.daor devap-enots eht otno dna spets eht nwod reh dewollof dna deerga flow detniap ehT .yellav eht ni hcum ees ot krad oot raf saw ti ,yks tsacrevo ,sselnoom eht htiW
.taorht sih deraelc eH ”—mU“ .mrots gniworg eht sdrawot tuo dekool eh dna dekcilf liat s’irokO ”.ffo dil eht ekat uoy ecno tsaf ytterp seird tI
,emit dnoces a roF
”?taht eveileb yllaer uoy oD“
gniht a si syob gnikcuf syoB
.llaw eht tsniaga kcab denael amihC ”.gnorw
mrots a ni ylil a sa flesmih denigami eH
detniap rehtona dna
.rekihhctih flowerew
dniw ehT ”.tcepser uoy nevig t’nevah I llik eno ton si erehT
.detuohs dna sredluohs eht yb lakcaj eht debbarg ihcakA  .od ot tfel gniht eno ylno saw erehT
.ezag eht gninruter ytluciffid dah lakcaj ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.ecnarongi ylno
.denworf eh dna kcab dedlof erew srae siH
.dnuora kool dna pu tis ot mih decrof traeh sseltser sih ,yllautnevE
tsniaga dnats ot yticadua s’roirraw a yb desaelp si noosnoM meht fo emos nI
revo depmil amihC
.roolf eht no tlep dekaos won eht otno delbmuts yeht dna dekcarc gninthgiL
esu uoy t’ndluoW“
.kcab srae sih dedlof dna nwod dekool amihC
.niaga elkcirp ruf sih gnikam ,dehsalf gninthgiL
.daor eht detcetorp taht sknab enots devrac eht ot pu
pu sworg eh nehw od ot nam a rof gniht reporp a toN
.swap s’rehto yb deliopsnu
”.irokO rof deirrow s’ehs dnA“
.ihcakA ecarbme ot nar flow detniap ehT ”!seY“
”?em htiw klaw uoy dluoW“
,ynoclab eht fo llaw enots wol eht no tser ot pu emac irokO
”?tcelloc uoy stlep noil eht tuoba tahw dnA“
rehtien nrettap a saw tI
,dnatsrednu ylluf t’nod ew taht sdne ot
.citats htiw gnilkcarc ruf sih ees ot nwod dekool eH
.secalkcen eht fo eno koot dna deddon ihcakA
.yellav eht revo dekool eH
.thgil gnidnilb htiw denrub swap sih
”,em tsurt yeht dna ,uoy tsurt I“
.mih ediseb dnats ot tuo emac itiwA ,rebmahc licnuoc eht tfel eh nehw tuB
.ynoclab eht morf dehctaw eh sa htrof dna kcab ylsuovren dekcilf liat s’ihcakA dna delbmur rednuht tnatsiD
.dnuora gnikool erofeb daeh sih koohs ihcakA
,noacyL édoyaK yb
”.snalc noil eht tuoba od ot tahw swonk esle eno on dna mra s’rihaT detsiwt itiwA“ .rehtorb sih ediseb hcneb eht no tas ihcakA ”.etiuq toN“
”,ikuH“ ”?siht si tahW“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,egaruoc on si ereht ,ti tuohtiw esuaceb ,ti ecarbmE
gnuoy tlef mih dnuora gnihtyrevE .seilil eulb fo
.knilb ot gnisufer ,tnerrot eht otni pu dekool eH .gnikaerb ton tub—gnirettulf latep—
gninthgil fo senil dekrof gniward detrats amihC .deniatnoc ti tniap esiouqrut eht ni sregnif rieht deppid meht fo htob dna
”?yldab dne t’nod seirots esoht fo ynam woh tsuJ“
.desuap irokO ,smra s’ihcakA
.srae sih ni gnignir eht raelc ot gniyrt ,daeh sih koohs irokO
.serif gnikooc morf esor ekomS
a era uoY .raef ni emahs on si erehT“
.elzzum ot elzzum
htiw tsenoh ylluf neeb t’nevah uoY“
.elims ecrof a htiw dias amihC ”.era uoy nehw ydaeR“
dedoolf yletelpmoc dah sdleif tsewol ehT
.flesruoy ot nem tcartta dna snoil redrum uoy taht
.esolc lakcaj eht dellup flow detniap ehT
.scigam taerg dleiw uoY
.hteet noil fo secalkcen owt htiw revo gnimoc ,dias amihC
.egnaro dna ,etihw ,kcalb ni mih derevoc yeht
rehtorb siH .puc nedoow a morf retaw ylil gnilknirps saw irokO .sdaeb
,namahS eht amihC rehtorb sih dna
.slakcaj regnuoy eht fo ynam gnoma ecneulfni elbaredisnoc dah ehs ,retsamraeps a sa ,tub licnuoc eht fo srebmem tsewen eht fo eno saw itiwA .ylmlac dias itiwA
thgil a ,eciov a fo daetsnI
.rehtorb sih ta derats eh dna kcab dedlof srae s’ihcakA ”.tcepsersid dna yticadua neewteb enil yldaed dna niht yrev a s’erehT“ ”.reh
.nruter ni stlep rieht su sevael ehs ,noosnoM ot seidob rieht reffo
.ksir eht ekat ot gnilliw saw ohw
”?mra sih detsiwt yllaretiL“
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
”,kaeps mih raeh ot ekil dluow I“
”?ylisae tahT“ ”.deerga yehT“
.ruf sih tsniaga toh gninrub tniap eht tlef eH
.did amihC sa stirips htiw enummoc
.yltalf dias amihC ”,htaeD“
.seirots eht fo tsom wonk I ,namahs a sA“
fo tseirP“   yojne esaelP
,egalliv lakcaj a gnoma seegufer flow detniap
.retal siht tuoba lla uoy hcaet ll’ew ,yrrow t’noD“
”.mih esoohc dluow uoy derugif I“
.ytpme ton era tsurt ew sesimorp rof
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     ”.si ti seY .seY“
.lautir siht fo sksir eurt eht em llet oS“
.sredle rehto eht morf esor tnemeerga fo elbmur lareneg A
.ylteiuq dias ihcakA ”,irokO“
.dedeen eh sruoh wef eht rof semoh rieht ni hguone efas eb dluohs enoyrevE
dna roolf eht no tam warts a tuo dial dah amihC ynoclab eht ot nepo moor gnittis eht nI .enots gnignahrevo eht fo retlehs evitaler eht rednu kcab deppets dna dewollaws eH .llaf ot detrats—
ygolohtna yrruf cirotsiherp gninniw-drawa eht ni derutaef seirots neetruof fo eno
.etihw gnidnilb a dehsalf sekirts gninthgil suoiruF
”.noitnetta reh evah eW“
.sroloc wen s’lakcaj eht emoceb dluohs yeht ,dekrow lautir siht fI
.noissucsid eht derongi ihcakA ”.esruoc fO“
”.gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW“
”.terces t’nera yehT ?slautir eht nialpxe ot em tnaw uoy diD“
.nihc sih debbur amihC ”.eerht ro owT“
”.gniht siht od uoy erofeb srewsna tsenoh tnaw I tub“ ,deilper itiwA
.etairporppani si tI“ .detrons itiwA
.deksa amihC ”?og ti did woH“  .pohskrow eht ni pmal lio eht morf gnirekcilf emalf llams a fo thgis eht ta dexaler srae siH .level tsehgih s’egalliv eht ssorca etulf s’rehtorb sih fo enord eht dewollof ihcakA ,niagA   ”.lautir
”.gnorts era uoy dna evarb era uoy rebmemeR“
.spord niar llams ward ot woh no irokO gnitcurtsni elihw
.seye reh otni dekool dna redluohs s’lakcaj eht no wap a detser ihcakA ”.t’nod
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.ytisoiruc htiw rehtegot sregnif sih desserp lakcaj ehT
.seye sih gnuts spord gnihsarc ehT ”.lakcaj siht
”.gniwonk ton reippah m’I kniht I“
eht fo ynam evigrof ot gnilliw si rihaT neve ,enola taht roF
”.trosnoc ym eb lliw uoy dnA“
.levorg t’nod seiliL
.eerga ylpmis dna noitidart fo og tel dluoc eh
dniw tew ,toh eht dna
ylevitatnet deksa eh ”?irokO“  .flow
.gnorw ti teg ll’I gniyrrow peek dna hcum oot wonk I
tlep etihw a htiw ti derevoc
.ruf dna sdap wap ot gnignilc ylnrobbuts saw taht mlif ykcits a otni gniyrd saw tniap ehT
.llaw nrehtuos s’yellav eht no hgih detnalp
,wen saw dlrow eht fi sa lativ dna
.eraperp ot tfel gnihton saw erehT
,noacyL édoyaK yb ”seiliL
.top yalc llams a pu dekcip rehtorb sih sa ylper t’ndid tub deffuh ihcakA ”.tnatropmi fo dnik saw tahT .doog hO“
,derepsihw eh ”,ereh s’ehS“
”.eerht yletinifed s’ti ,oN“
.sredavni eb-dluow morf yellav eht gnidih fo tifeneb elbissop eht rof elbaeganam saw ksir ehT
,tniap raw fo daetsnI
.sevlesmeht dna dlrow eht gnirolpxe llits era yeht nehw od seippup
.rewop ruoy fo ewa ni dekauq seenk ym ,niar yrevE“
.rae s’lakcaj eht ni derepsihw dna tlep eht no nwod ecaf irokO dellor ihcakA .dewolg ruf sih no tniap egnaro dna etihw eht tub
?siht od ot gniog er’ew woh saedi ynA“
.stuh rieht ni retlehs nekat dah yellav eht ni slakcaj eht fo tsom dna thgis ni tirips a ton saw erehT
.seye s’irokO otni dekool ihcakA dna
.mih erofeb gnidnats
,lakcaj a llits saw irokO
ylesolc rehto hcae dleh yehT
”.evah thgim uoy swalf
,retal syad eerhT   ”.etsaw
enob llams fo slessat htiw degde
.sraet neddus tsniaga deffins dna
evah I dnA“ .mih sdrawot denrut itiwA ”.sdnal eseht ni erar si hcihw ,tseirp a dna roirraw a er’uoY“ .deksa ihcakA ”?detcejbo enoyna t’nsah yhw nehT“
.dewollaws irokO ”,yakO“
.uoy dnuorrus taht stirips eht nees
.noitcetorp rof ,tirips lufrewop a
.kcab srae sih dedlof iorkO ”.llew tuo nrut lliw gnihtyreve dna em ediseb dnatS“
.ylfnogard eulb yltsohg a ees
”.deifirret m’I“
”?wonk ot ekil uoy dluow tahW“
.ylper ot lakcaj eht rof tiaw t’ndid eH
,gnidnats llits saw esuoh ehT
.doolb sesu lautir yreve ton ,dias rehtorb ym ekil ,lleW“ ”?taht rof doolb
.’yliL eht fo elpoeP’ eht—ayinovA era eW
tsim a tsomla—elzzird
.ylmrif detats lakcaj eht
.dekcilf liat s’ihcakA
.tnacifingisni dna
.evoba asem eht kcuts gninthgil sa ria eht derettahs kcarc gnidnuoser a neht dna elkcirp ot detrats ruf siH
”seiliL fo tseirP“
”.nosaes fo tuo siht ekil mrots a nees reven ev’I“
,drawrof srae sih denrut eH
.nosaes siht tsevrah dnoces a tneverp dluow sdoolf ehT
.tnemom a rof denworf ehS
.tlep eht fo ruf etihw eht tsniaga wolg ot demees retaw ylil fo sdaeb eht ,roolf eht nO
.ylevitatnet ti koot irokO .ecalkcen rehto eht tuo dleh dna dias amihC
”!noosnoM“ .emit saw tI
”.uoy erew os tuB“ .pu dekool amihC
”.elpmis dnuos ti ekam uoY“
.os enod syawla evah ayinovA ehT“ .ruos
.rehtorb sih ta eralg ot pu dekool ihcakA
,emit tsaL  .kni.sfhf
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
ot seye sih denepo ihcakA dna srae sih tsap derettulf yltneg tirips ylil A
.deksa ihcakA ”?ydaer uoy erA“
,noacyL édoyaK yb
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT