,derepsihw eh ,eugnot nwo reh ni ,yltneG
.irokO ot kcab gninrut erofeb rehtorb sih ta yldetniop dekool amihC
.yellav eht ot ecnartne eht gnitcetorp llaw eht no draug gnidnats slakcaj eerht tsap deklaw dna htap enots eht dehcaer eH
.sselduolc ylraen saw yks eulb ehT
.kcab dennip srae sih dna denediw seye s’amihC ”.enod evah snalc eht lla rof egnever detnaW
,pot eht ot tog eh nehW
.erom tsevrah ot yaw on dah eh dna suoicerp erew yehT
.did yllausu eh ekil
,dekramer ihcakA ”.ti
,sriats eht morf tniop tsehtruf eht
ayinovA eht fo eno thguof reven dah ehS
s’erehT .su ylno si ereht tuB“
.wap a ni strad sih dna redluohs sih revo tlep a htiw yellav eht ot denruter ihcakA
.efink sih pu dekcip flow detniap ehT .tneitapmi
saw sihT .tnemom yna ta egnahc dluoc dniw eht tub ,dniwnwod saw eH
,daor eht nwod deunitnoc dna tuh s’rennat eht ta tlep s’noil eht ffo deppord eH .emoh saw eh
.gnimoc erew sniar ehT
”.ecnadiug rof gniksa eno eht er’uoY“
.top yalc a htiw devirra irokO nehw yks eht ni wol saw nus ehT
,htaerb sih rednu sreyarp eht gnitaeper
”?ssecorp eht ni yellav eritne eht gniyortsed
”.lausu naht erom oN“
”.enob dna hself eht gnireffo erofeb reh mialc ot noosnoM rof detiaw  I“ .deffins eH
.baj eht derongi amihC
.eson sih hguorht tuo deffuh eH
.yellav daorb eht sdrawot wap sih gnivaw ,deilper ihcakA ”,wonk I“ ”.tseirp a deen yeht ,namahs a sa od nac I hcum t’nsi
”.llew og yltcaxe t’ndid tahT“
deraperp dah rehtorb sih eerht fo eno—
.seye sih debbur eh sa deerga ihcakA ”,saw tI“
”,aet eht knird dna hctaW“  .deksa irokO
.sih ni ecilam yna regnol on saw ereht ees dluoc ehs depoh eH
.noitnetta yap ot gnuoy oot tub wob s’retnuh a esu ot hguone gnorts saw ehS“
.evah reve d’eh tsal eht eb yam yeht
spiy fo esruoc a htiw deteerg saw eh ,spets worran fo tes tsrif eht dehcaer eh retfA
.enots dehsawetihw eht tsniaga denael dna mih dniheb ni depmil flow detniap rehto ehT .hsaw
,ayinovA eht naht setamkcap rieht sdrawot evisuffe ssel erew slakcaJ
”seiliL fo tseirP“   yojne esaelP
”.em morf yawa gnippils si
”.emit ynA“ ”.uoy knahT“
.gnuoy saw ehs sa hsiloof sa saw ehS
.yks elprup sselduolc a gnivael
.niaga spil sih ot etulf eht thguorb amihC ”.dooG“
.eert eht fo edahs eht tfel dna pu doots ihcakA
.slatep ylil eerht dleh ylno tleb sih no hcuop ehT
.lufegnev ton tub ,gnivigrofnu dna
”,deksa uoy ekil srebme emos thguorB“
ot moorkrow s’amihC otni gnippets
.mih edulcni nac eW“
rof doots ehs tahw tub
,lliks htiw evlos dluoc eh gnihtemos ton
.deksa ihcakA ”?gnis I fi dniM“
ot gnihctelf emos dda uoy sselnu sulyts a raen erehwyna em teg ot gniog ton er’uoy dna
.maercs ot htaerb eht ward regnol on dluoc tub ,llef ehS
.thgiliwt ta stirips emos llac nac eW“
dil eht devomer eH
nalp enasni s’rehtorb sih sevivrus ihcakA fi tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,evitcudorp-retnuoc eb dluow ecalkcen yduag nwo sih htiw redle eht gnitaeB
lakcaj a egnahc t’nac ew nosaer ynA“
.noosnoM fo tseirp a m’I“
.snalc noil eht fo swalc gnipsarg eht rof ton fi
.daeh s’lakcaj eht no ruf eht delffur amihC
”.pleh lliw gnisselb a ebyaM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dias ihcakA ”,oga emit gnol a stirips redneval eht deksa evah dluohs eW .gnizamA“
”.niaga teem ew nehw ecaep dnif ew yaM“
.srieht sa demialc yeht was yeht gnihtyrevE
.pohskrow eht morf eldnub llams a
.deksa amihC ”?leef uoy od woH“
ygolohtna yrruf cirotsiherp gninniw-drawa eht ni derutaef seirots neetruof fo eno ,noacyL édoyaK yb ”seiliL fo tseirP“
.dniw eht ni gniwolb ssarg naht erom gnihton saw ereht ,neeb dah srae sih erehW .mih gnidih
.tsrif ta rehtorb sih dna mih tpecca ot tnatiseh neeb dah sredle eht fo llA
,meht dedeeh ehs fI
nwod etulf sih tes eH
.drawrof ylevitnetta denrut srae s’rehtorb siH
.htolcniol dna ruf sih gniniats doolb reh
.wap eerf won sih htiw erutseg eht denruter
.deraeppa htom rehtonA .aet pis
.sthguoht s’rehtorb sih gnitpurretni
.yas ot erom gnihton saw erehT
.sdleif eht gnidnet slakcaj eht gnihctaw ,ynoclab eht fo egde enots eht no tas ihcakA ,gninrom txen eht etaL
.ezorf flow detniap ehT
”?doolb fo tol a eb ot gniog ereht sI“
.rof doots ehs tahw detaH“
.ltalta sih fo rups eht ot—
.worht eht etelpmoc ot tsirw sih deppans eh nehT
.gnitiaw ,eert eht ediseb tlenk flow detniap ehT
.dnik rieht fo tnemevalsne rehtruf eht tsniaga doots taht lla erew sllaw esehT
.nwo rieht dellac yeht dleif a dah ylimaf tseroop eht nevE
”.seilil eht deen I“
.sevals rieht emoceb dluow deniamer ohw slakcaj yna dna
asem der gnirewot a saw ,daor enots eht fo dne eht ta ,yellav eht fo edis raf eht nO
ltalta sih ot strad gnol sih fo eno gnikcoN .ydaer t’nsaw eH
.sruoh ekat dluow nosiop eht ,gnihton did eh fI
”?taht tegrof uoy did woH“
.ssertrof a saw ti ,emoh a dna egalliv a tsuj t’nsaw ti tub
,sknaht sih derepsihw ihcakA
”.erofeb lautir a rof pu em detivni t’nevah uoY .erus…hU“
,reh ediseb deyats eH
”,esiw ton saw …tahT“
”.smelborp ruo fo tsom evlos dluow taht
;mih democlew dah seilil ,htaed htiw deniats nevE
.gnitairufni saw étevïan tnagorra s’lakcaj ehT
.pu ti dleh eh sa wap sih ni dloc tsomla saw ltalta ehT
,yks eht ni hgih nus eht htiw ,retal sruoH
.roirraw a ton saw ehS .mih fo tnorf ni ereht doots noil ehT .ytip tlef ihcakA
.kcab srae sih dedlof ihcakA ”.aedi dab a neeb evah dluow tahT“
.drawrof trad eht gnivird—mra sih gnigniws dna ydob sih gninrut ,drawrof deppets ihcakA
.yad nosaes-yrd etal a fo taeh noonretfa eht ni
.warts htiw deffuts wollip a revo tlep nedlog a no tas amihC
,mih dnuora rettulf ot emac stirips ylil depahs-ylfnogard eulb nehT
”?sniatnuom eht otni emoc ton od yeht os
.slatep fo duolc a ni dehsinav neht dna detarbiv shtom ehT .murd sih fo egde eht deppat amihC
.mih fo tnorf ni top eht delttes dna tlep eht fo egde eht ot flesmih dils flow detniap ehT
,enoyreve htiw sgaw dna skcil gnignahcxe retfA
.efil a fo gnikat eht gnirrohba
retaw naelc fo tnecs gnimoclew eht ,revir eht ediseb nwod emac htap neddort-llew eht erehW
.pu dekool eh dna daehrevo dekaorc erutluv a yllautnevE
gnillewd moor-eerht denoitroporp ylsuoreneg a nevig neeb dah sevlow detniap eht
,seitic gnilwarps rieht fo sllaw eht dniheb efas ,snalc noil ehT
”.su nekasrof t’nevah stirips eht fo tser eht tsael tA“ .dehgis ihcakA ”.evah uoy lla s’taht fI“
drawrof deklaw ihcakA
.mih edih ot stirips eht gnitsurt ,ssarg eht hguorht dedaw eH
.raf oot deppets dah ohw retnuh rehtonA
.edisa htolc eht tes ihcakA
.seilil fo tseirp s’ebirt eht emoceb dluow yllausu yeht ,trosnoc a koot noosnoM fo tseirp a nehW .gnirebmemer ,daeh sih detlit ihcakA ”?ti od ot hguonE
.ti yned yltnemehev dluow ohw ,rihaT rof neve—ylimaf emoceb dah pihsdneirF
.nwonknu t’nerew sgniriap redneg emas ro desrever hguoht ,ylevitcepser elamef dna elam yllausU
.gniggaw sliat ,revo nar dna edisa sraeps trohs dna sdleihs rekciw egral rieht tes yeht
.dniw eht fo gnillits neddus eht ro rae kcalb a fo thgis tsrif eht ta enorp deppord evah dluow ehs
,tlep wolley ,tfos a no gnittis ot devom dah tub ynoclab eht no llits erew sevlow detniap ehT
.rekaew emaceb pleh rof seirc reh sa
”.thginot dnuora em gnivah dnim t’nod uoy epoH“
.kcab eb ot doog saw tI
.aet sih fo tsal eht knard dna delims amihC ”.dekrow ti nehT“
”?nosaes fo tuo ,flesreh noosnoM nommus ot em tnaw uoY“
.ecneuqesnoc on fo eb dluow sdrawretfa mih ot deneppah tahW
.niap eht dna rorret eht ees dluoc eh ,seye reh nI
.htolcniol sih no swap sih gnipiw ,detnemmoc amihC
,reit driht eht nO
.enob hgiht s’noil a fo tuo devrac saw ltalta sih tub
”—ton ro gnidnatsrednU“ ”.dnatsrednu yehT
”?ylrae os ereh pu uoy era yhW“.ekops
”.seilil eht tespu evah dluow tI“ ”?yhW“
”.ecitcarp ot tnaw uoy fi sllorcs fo elpuoc a tfel eH
”.redneval emos evah od I tuB“ .dias amihC
.pu tog flow detniap rehto eht erofeb rehtorb sih delzzun ihcakA
.kni.sfhf
.daeh sih detlit amihC
”?od ot em tnaw uoy od tahW“
ot sriats eht sdrawot denrut ihcakA
.derepsorp yeht ,dekool eh erehwyreve dna yellav eht ni devil slakcaj fo sdnasuohT
.dnik reh fo ecnagorra dna ecnarongi eht—
”.pleh dluow ti ,etatidem nac uoy fI“
.mih raeh dluoc ohw gnirac ton—delworg ihcakA ”,tnemugra siht dah ev’eW“
yellav eritne eht gniyortsed ksir d’ew
?yap regnol on nac uoy litnu gnol woH
,mih tuoba snoitavreser dah ohw tfel sredle wef eht fo eno saw rihaT .tsap eht no detcelfer eh ,slakcaj rellams eht dnuora deppets dna debmilc ylwols eh sA
eh dna ,dah sdraug eht sa tcepser ni stsehc rieht pmuht ot krow rieht morf pu dekool slakcaj wef A
litnu rehto hcae ta derats yehT
.level dnoces eht htaeneb enots eht otni devrac esuoh egral eht sdrawot yawa deklaw yldetniop dna ,eson sih
.mih delzzun dna elims derit a lakcaj eht evag ihcakA
.digir emoceb ot bmil tsrif eht saw gel tfel reH
.slevel rellams dna
thgit dellup elcsum yreve sa dehcra kcab ,dnuorg eht no gnihtirw saw ehs ,reh dehcaer eh nehW
.erom enod evah dluow yeht ,desselb neeb dah eh fI
”?owt ro raey a ni taht od snalc noil eht rehtar uoy dluoW“
.tsal eht naht reivaeh tlef pets hcaE
”.em fo espmilg a thguaC
.stseirp reh ot gnivig os ton saw noosnoM dna
eh neht ,htaerb peed a koot dna seye sih desolc eH
.srewolf eulb fo aes a emoceb evah dluow revir nellows eht ,emit a roF
.sgel sih gninaelc trats ot htolc eht pu dekcip ihcakA ”.htaed kciuq a reh gnivig erofeb krow ot nosiop eht rof detiaw ylno I
,yakO“ .yawa dekool dna dehguoc ihcakA
.epoh eb dluow ereht ,devil eh sa gnol sA
.deneppah gnihton ,tnemom a roF
”.gnidnatsrednu emos evah redneval dna slakcaJ
.taht tsuj enod dah lakcaj eht nehw
ta noitamrofni erom etavacxE
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,noacyL édoyaK yb ”seiliL
.spup ecudorp ot gnilpuoc eht rof tnemeriuqer on dah sniar eht fo dne eht ta htriber fo lautir ehT
,seilil fo tseirp a emaceb uoy nehW“
tor dluow sdees eht ,won tuB
,edis rehtie ot denrut srae
.ereht doots tsuj dnA“
.murd sih pu gnikcip erofeb spuc llams eerht neewteb aet eht dedivid amihC
.yrotirret erom laets ot swalc rieht tuo gnihcaer reve erew
,srieht ton erew ayinovA eht fo syaw ehT
yellav eht no mialc rieht ekats dluow snalc eht ,sraey wef a nI
.hcum oot tsuj s’tI“
,yletelpmoc dneb t’ndid eenk tfel siH
”,tfel slatep ylil yna evah t’nod I“
.kcab srae sih dedlof amihC ”.yadretsey
.noitisop sih yawa evig dluow
.meop tneicna na gniticer detrats dna
”?kcab gnimoc erofeb ehtab t’ndid uoY“
elbatrofmoc tsomla
.teef sih decalp dna htaerb peed a koot flow detniap ehT
daer ot gninrael emit ym dneps ot od ot sgniht ynam oot evah I“
.dekcilf srae sih nehT
desseug flow detniap eht—noil regnuoy A
.esruc a kcab tib eH
,ecnagavartxe na eb dluow tI
.ynoclab eht no dednecsed meht fo duolc gnilriws a nehT
ecnelis ni dessap etunim a tsomla dna
.lakcaj eht deksa amihC ”?leef uoy od woH“
,revo saw selpoep rieht neewteb raW taerG ehT
.etsap kcalb ykcits a ni derevoc saw
.deksa ihcakA ”?thginot uoy eeS“
.ylteiuq dias ihcakA ”,wonk I“
.esuoh rieht otni deklaw dna
.stirips eht fo yaw eht ni srehto niart dluoc ohw eno on dah yeht
;namahs a dnif ot etarepsed neeb dah egalliv eht tub
.mih sdrawot ylirgna gnidirts senots sipal gnikcalc fo ecalkcen yvaeh a gniraew lakcaj ylredle na ees ot dnuora denrut ihcakA .tsop sih ot kcab nar eh neht
”—eno siht ,sediseB
”.taht wonk uoY .yrroS“ .srae sih dekcilf eh nehT .yltfos dias amihC
.lakcaj eht evoba gnirewot ,thgieh lluf sih ot pu doots flow detniap ehT
mih dnuora delriws tsug neddus A
”.thginot emoc ot irokO deksa I“
,tuc elgnis a htiW
.sdrow sih no dekohc ihcakA “.amihC
hsrah saw erutaN .retteb wenk eH
erofeb keew eht fo yromem ni delims ihcakA
,htiw krow ot nevoc a dah I fi nevE“ .dewollaws ihcakA
.werg pihsdneirf dna denessel noicipsus ,sraey eht revO
.detarapes yeht erofeb htaerb delahxe wols eno rof deniwtretni seugnot riehT
.dnuorg eht ot deppord dna demaercs ehS   .pih reh fo tnioj eht edisni tsuj
.redneval fo tnecs eht htiw ria eht gnillif ,gniliob saw retaw eht ,nooS
”?elbissop s’ti oS“
.yadretsey edam ehs daerb tiurf eht fo emos em thguorb auqaN“ ”?tae uoy diD“
”.gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.latep yna naht erom htrow saw efil sih ,os nevE
.elbat krow eht evoba flehs eht ta detniop dna dennirg flow detniap ehT
noitnem I diD“  .desserp amihC
.retal deneppah tahT“
.tser eht fo erac ekat stnavres degniw reh tel neht dna noosnoM ot seitud sih llifluf dluow eH
gnirepsihw ,rae sih dehsurb dniw fo dnarts a dna
”.pu ekow tsuj I ekiL“
.derettulf sgniw tneculsnarT
.reggad sih tuo dellup
;wonk dluow ehs ,woN
”.egalliv eht fo tuo su worht ot gniog era sredle eht fo tser eht dna enasni si aedi sihT“ .dennirg amihC
”,gnimaercs eb ot gniog si rihaT hcum woh tuoba kniht tsuJ“ ”.oN“
.asem eht otni devrac
egalliv eht fo slevel tsehgih eht edam edahs dna ezeerb ehT
,secifircas etairporppa eht dna
.tuo derats dna ynoclab eht otno tuo deppets eH
”?uoy gnirehtob gel ruoy sI ?yhW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.meht emalb t’ndluoc eH
.elims thgils a htiw deilper flow detniap rehto eht ”,teY“
.elbisiv gnimoceb erew srats tsethgirb ehT
tsrif eht no devil sredle eht fo lla erehw morf klaw tnatsid ,gnol a saw tI
,reh ta ton ;traeh sih ni etah ot denrut tpmetnoC
selkcah siH .ffo deppord eh tlep eht tuoba rihaT dlot evah tsum enoemoS
stsim suoicilam ,dloc denommus evah dluow seilil fo tseirp a yb swap eht ni dleh rewolf elgnis a ,raw eht gniruD
.gel emal sih etipsed dah eh lla dereffo yleerf—amihC—rehtorb siH
.eert aicaca daorb a fo edahs eht sdrawot yaw sih edam ylwols dna denrut eH
.dehcaorppa ihcakA sa
sih elihw noil eht no seye sih tpek eH
”.t’nod enim fo tsom
.deirrac ehs wob egral eht morf retnuh a ylbaborp—
.noosnoM fo tseirp a ron—
.gnidaer emos did ew dna pu emac ugeB“
edaf gnos sih tel ihcakA
.flesmih gnicnuonna tuohtiw ni deklaw eh sa deggaw liat s’lakcaj gnuoy ehT
.etulf s’rehtorb sih fo enord lufnruom eht draeh eh sa delims ihcakA .level
.doolb eht tpecxe gnihtyna—tuoba klat ot gnihtemos rof gnipsarg
”.gnizama saw tahT“
erehT“ .denworf dna deddon amihC
.enola saw ehs erus ekam ot gninetsil
.eunitnoc ot flesmih gnirb ton dluoc eh tub
.deziremsem ,tas irokO
,thgis fo tuo saw rihaT retfA
,deksa amihC ”?trosnoc a sa lakcaj a ekat t’nac uoy nosaer yna ereht sI“
.noosnoM fo tseirp a er’uoy
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.yaw taht neeb syawla t’ndah ti tub
.tsal did uoy tahw raey siht eciwt diap uoY“
!su dnuora sniatnuom eht dna
”.sriatspu gniog m’I
.kcab srae sih dedlof dna nwod dekool rehtorb siH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.egalliv eht sevas ro
rehgih ylgnisaercni eht gnitcennoc spets worran ylno htiw ,kcor eht otni peed devrac erew sreit ruof eht fo hcaE
.yrt ot dah eh tub ,meht tsniaga enola dnats dluoc elpoep on ,ebirt oN
.tpmetnoc ot yaw evag ytiP
,deppots sdniw eht nehT
deggas srae s’ihcakA ”?klat ot ydaer uoY“
uoy era tahW“ .esor
,yellav eht fo dne raf eht sdrawot detniop eh
.elpoep nwo sih fo gniteerg lanoitidart eht ni swaj rieht delzzun dna meht revo gninael diova ot tlenk flow detniap ehT
.ekops eh yllaniF
.sduolc eht tsniaga mrof reh gnithgilhgih ,pu dnats ot noil eht rof gnol ekat t’ndid tI
.ynoclab eht tsap tuo kool ot denrut amihC
.ti htiw daeh sih gnibburcs detrats dna retaw fo lwob egral a otni htolc a deppid eh sa
,detiaw sdrib dercas eht fo eerhT
”?yhW .trosnoc eht otni luos s’tseirp eht fo trap dna tirips ylil a segrem taht gninommus ronim a s’tI“
.ereht eb dluow eh ,llef ehs nehW
”.doolb fo tol a s’tahT“
liat sih gaw t’ndid tub nruter ni tsehc sih depmuht eH
?seilil eht gnittespu em tuoba gniklat er’uoy dnA“
”.ylimaf ruo gnillik snoil eht rof su emalb llits yehT“
”,gninetsil dna seye ruoy gnisolc yrT“ ”.yrt ll’I“
eurt welf trad ehT
”.gnivigrof ton si noosnoM .nosaer a rof slautir evah eW
.reh hguorht depees nosiop eht ,ylwolS
.htaerb rieht gnidloh fi sa
.mih ot txen tis ot tuo deklaw rehtorb sih sa revo dekool flow detniap ehT .meht gnoma eciov s'irokO tuo kcip ot mih rof tnatsid oot erew sdnuos ehT
ylper t’ndid ihcakA
.meht morf ssorca tas dna dias irokO
.ylhsrah derepsihw rihaT ”?!gniod
.elzzum sih nwod gnidils sraet htiw
.tsiaw sih dnuora liat sih delruc eH
fo tseirP“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     ”?tahw yM“
.ylneve dias rehtorb sih
.swap sih ni daeh sih deirub ihcakA
”,doolb evlovni slautir ayinovA lla toN“
?lautir noitanoroc eht rebmemer uoy oD
,rae reh depsarg dna reh ediseb tlenk eH
.rae na dniheb dehctarcs flow detniap ehT
.eid dluow ehs neht
fo etir ruoy tsap tsuj uoy
.loots nedoow wol a no detser toof sih os
.pih reh no reviuq eht morf worra na tuo dellup ehs dna mih sdrawot dehctiwt srae s’noil ehT
.dias ihcakA ”?egassap
.secap eerht-ytneves—
,oga gnol ,ecno ti enod dah eH
”.ereh evil ot rabatovaL morf enoyna teg ot yaw on
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,llik ysae na rof sekam taht
.roirraw a fo esoht erofeb emac tseirp a sa seitud sih dna dercas saw efil llA
.ylyrd dias amihC
.deniart draug nwot eht sa stnurg dna stuohs erew ereht ,level tsrif eht nO
sraey eerht rof niarg hguone dleh sevac peed
.traeh reh dessim I dna worht gnol a saw tI .t’ndid I“
,sreyarp eht dias ,eye eht ni reh dekooL“
”.oga emitefil a ekil mees slautir ylil ehT“
dna retaw fo top reppoc a eveirter ot pu doots ihcakA .srebme eht pu derrits dna
.drawrof srae rieht tpek dna yellav eht ot kcab noitnetta rieht denrut dah sdraug ehT
,etubirt reviled ydaerla ew taht uoy rof hguone ton ti sI
ltalta sih dnuora denethgit wap siH
,sniatnuom eht woleb dils nus ehT
”.yawa klaw sruoh eerht ton saw—“
”,taht od uoy nehw ekil t’nod seilil ehT“
.ti gnitcetorp stsim eht hguorht yellav eht dnif dluoc tnetni-lli htiw nosrep on ,seilil fo tseirp lufhtiaf a htiW
.gnithgif enod t’nsaw eH
”.ti gnisol m’I“ .ekops eh erofeb
”,tseb eb dluow tahT“
.neeb dah ti naht reidaets dna
wol dehcuorc eh dna
.ylteiuq dias ihcakA
.stniap gnikam trats ll’I“
”.yrtsihpos ruoy ecitcarp dluohs uoy dnA
.gnireffo sih sa gnos eltneg a gnirepsihw ,sdap wap sih neewteb ti dehsurc dna tuo eno dellup eH
.msaisuhtne lauqe htiw noitceffa sih denruter yeht ,mih rof tub
.srae sih morf niard doolb eht tlef ihcakA ”?ayinovA na otni
”.detrats teg nac ew dna srebme eht em dnaH“
,mih fo tnorf ni shtgnel-mra owt ,daeh tnilf ehT
.pleh rieht rof stirips eht ksa ot tnatculer saw eh tub
,lleW“ .enots eht tsniaga liat sih dekcams dna kcab srae sih dennip ihcakA ”…yruf s’noosnoM fo secneuqesnoc ehT
.hguone saw ti tub ,hcum t’nsaw tI
.irokO revo deregnil eh
.mih dednuorrus srewolfdliw dna
.daeh sih ffo gnuh srae siH
.elzzum sih tsniaga dehsurb tirips ylil a nehw gnas ti ,traeh sih fo ssenivaeh eht etipseD
erofeb meht ot txen htolcniol dna tleb sih tes dna llaw eht fo renroc eht tsniaga pu strad sih denael flow detniap ehT
”…t’ndid uoy em llet esaelP“
.tcepser ni stsehc rieht tsniaga stsif dehcnelc rieht pmuht ot gniyalp neeb dah yeht emag revetahw morf pu dekool yehT
.level dnoces eht
.thgif ot elba regnol on—
.efil ot meht xaoc ot seilil fo tseirp eltneg a tuohtiw
.rehtorb sih ta derats dna deknilb ihcakA ”.noosnoM
.noitseuq eht deredisnoc eh sa dexaler srae s’ihcakA ”?evitamrofsnart gnihtyna od lautir noitanoroc eht seoD“
.egaugnal s’lakcaj eht fo spots dna senot rehsrah eht dekcal egaugnal ayinovA eht
,ylleb reh otni peed dna wol daeh tnilf sti deirub dna
.su no nwod snalc eht gnirb ll’uoY“
.retaw raelc ,dloc htiw gnirps a deretlehs dna
trad gnol a dekcon dna eert eht dehcaer eH
.nerdlihc nethgirf ot seirots tub gnihton erew stsim eht morf snomed ehT
”.ereh uoy evah ot dalG“
;elzzum sih morf ylhtooms dewolf doohdlihc sih fo sdrow eht dna eugnot evitan sih ni rehgih evatco na saw eciov siH
t’nereW“ ”?xis ti saw ro—sniar eviF“
.gnignis detrats eh nehT
”.od ot desoppus m’I sgniht eht lla ;tlep reh koot
.gnihton dias rehtorb siH
.ecnatsid eht otni ffo gnirats ,dias amihC ”,haeY“
.sucof ot flesmih gnidnimer ,delahxe ihcakA
.sesuoh dum dnuor htiw sdleif daorb ot yaw evag seert erehw
ot gnimmurd deppots amihC
”.seilil naht pu kcuts sseL“ .dennirg amihC
.rehtorb sih ta dekool dna elzzum sih tsniaga etulf sih deppat amihC ”.stnuoc ylbaborp tahT“
,reh detah I“  .denworf amihC
.taeb gnitaeper elpmis a detrats eh sa dias amihC
,yawa welf stirips ylil eht
”,nwod tnew reven I“
,ylderit dias ihcakA ”,si ti seY“
.ylpeed delahni ihcakA
.ssarg llat eht ni
.meht neewteb murd emarf a dna wets fo top ytpme na
.ees dluoc eh sa raf sa htrae eht morf esor taht
.aet fo pis a koot dna taorht sih deraelc ihcakA .dedda amihC
.tnemmoc eht derongi flow detniap rehto ehT
.etir eht fo elahxe rebmos eht kaerb ot eno tsrif eht saw irokO
.deraeppa htom yltsohg elgnis A
dessap dah syad esoht tub
.yltnatiseh deilper ihcakA ”?seY“ ”.trosnoc reh sa uoy koot nryeW
.moolb dluow tnalp ot drah os dekrow yeht seilil eht dna yellav eht doolf dluow yeht ,llew enog dah lla fI
,level htruof eht fo dne enO
.edasilap nedoow a dniheb gnidnats slakcaj xis eht morf
regnorts saw eciov siH
.ti gninigami morf flow detniap eht pots t’ndid taht tub
;deriapsed traeh sih ,tnemom a roF
.ecaf sih ees dluoc ehs os daeh reh gninrut
.elzzum ot elzzum ssik dluoc yeht os daeh sih detlit lakcaj ehT
;nuf evah owt uoY“
.emahs tlef eh nehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ecnalab eht tub ,elpoep llik ot desoppus m’I wonk I .htaed hcum oS
.kcab dedlof srae s’lakcaj ehT
,liev eht dnoyeb dlrow eht ot luos reh ediug dluow taht sreyarp eht dias dna seye ytpme reh desolc flow detniap ehT
.ecnatsid eht ni noil a was eh sa noitanimreted htiw deneffits dna drawrof deleviws srae s’ihcakA .nus gninrom yzah a rednu ssarg hannavas yrd hguorht deltsur dniw ehT  2 fo 1 traP ,noacyL édoyaK yb
.seert fo retsulc a sdrawot dereggats dna trad eht fo tfah eht ffo ekorb noil ehT
;ti otni devrac egalliv a htiw
,gnikaeps hsinif dluoc eh erofeb ezorf liat s’lakcaj ehT ”—eY“
tuo deffuh ,tuhs waj sih deppans lakcaj eht
,lleW“ ”.yerp deltrats ekil ereht dootS
,taht fo gnikaepS“
.gniffins saw ehS
”?taht tegrof uoy dluoc woH“
.delbmuts eh dna eloh a otni deppils toof sih nehT
.dniw eht ni delppir gnihctelf rehtaef etihw s’trad ehT