.thgin eht ni evled ot   secaf krad fo htraed oN osla rof derac eb lliw   gnitiaw si taht doorb ehT
.nwad fo dlareh eht   ereh semoc erofeb ,flesreH ffutsdoof gnihsiruon fo   deen ehs sah won tuB
.gnihton sniag ti ,sekam ehS stroffe gnirobal dna   gnihcaer-gnol hguohT !salA
orevO ovitlA yb meop a ,”gnilworP noycorP“   yojne esaelP  .htims niatnuom eht
,ssih a ,elbmum A
,seirreb eht era neerg oot   reh dnuora gniworg llA
ovitlA yb si meop s’yadoT
.niaga ti sraen ehs sa   llew os ti swonk ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
uoy rof daer si dna
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer ,orevO ovitlA yb
.enon naht retteb tub   dednetni s’ti sdrib roF
redeef gnignah-llat eht ot   daert reh ehs sekat suhT
.tey tneluccus ron   denepir ton stoor teews ehT
.roop oot si thgis reh rof   llew os ton hcraeS
,ynam fo nortam siht roF
,sdrab noxaS-olgnA ylrae fo erutcurts citeop evitaretilla eht sesu hcihw ,orevO
,irauR nosmirC yb
.won reh rof erac tseb ot   tfel dna denodnabA
.neeuq nalc gniraeb-klim a
deriuqer eb lliw sa   gnihsaw rof retaw dnA
,ksam ecaf ni deirub   ,snottub ekil seye kcalB
.ni s’ehS .rettalc feirB
”gnilworP noycorP“ saw sihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,snac hsart eht ot snrut ehs dnA
rettam etsaw dna senob ni   gnitsaef reh pu kaerb oT semoc enon ,rednow tub   esiwrehto ti slliw rafA god a morf tnialpmoc A
.ecnanetsus rof gnihsiw
,syawklaw gnirednaW
ned emoh eht ni tsriht   nerdlihc deliat-gnir eerht reH
.htims niatnuom eht
.esoper ylenol ni   nwo rieht no evil oT
,nedrag dewed-revlis eht hguorht   sknils ehs ecnelis nI
doof si ereht erehw ot   dnaldoow hguorht gniklaW ,gnidael elif elgnis ni   ,meht wohs ehs lliw nooS
.esool si taht pot a