.noitacitsemod a dellac si sihT .sevlow gnieb deppots ew esuaceb snamuh otni snamuh-tsomla eht denrut eW
.oot sevlesmeht no tfilpu na od snamuh eht depleh eW .tfilpu na dellac si tahT
.sepahs raeh meht stel taht
.sdneirf doog eb ot woh meht gniwohs dna meht gniniart peek ot evah lliw eW
.sremmiws doog yllaer meht ekam sliat gib riehT .retaw eht ni evil yeht tub ,sgod ekil era yehT .snihplod dellac ,seiceps rehtona htiw sdneirf era eW snihploD
renoos yppah meht ekam nac uoY
.sgniht gniworht dna gnixif dna gnidliub ta doog yrev era snamuH
.seod yppup a ekil
,trams yrev dna doog yrev era snamuh tsoM
.erehwyna og tonnac taht spihs gib yllaer dliub ew ,semitemoS .ti ni ria s'tenalp a fo eceip a htiw xob latem a si hcihw ,pihs a ni edir ew
.sgniht kaerb yeht nehw tpecxe
.ylisae yrev dlo dna kcis teg ot desu eW
,tenalp a erolpxe ew nehW .ecaps retuo ot su htiw emoc yeht os
,sdnah rieht fo esuaceb si sihT
.sgel tobor rieht gnisu ,retaw eht morf su tisiv yehT
.meht rof dnuora nur ot evah ew os ,sgel owt evah ylno yeht esuaceb wols yrev era yehT .pleh fo stol deen yeht tub
.gnol rof klat dna yats ot ekil ton od snihplod eht tub ,snihplod eht tuoba nrael ot yrt sIA ehT
,ranos od ot lufesu si tI
kaeuqs laiceps a wonk snihplod ehT
,sgel tobor htiw nevE
.ria on sah ti esuaceb ecaps hguorht lwoh ro krab tonnac ew esuaceb doog era hcihw ,soidar ekil ,sloot doog rehto fo stol evah eW .sliat evah ew esuaceb ,hguoht ,sgnileef ruo erahs ydaerla dluoc eW
.stolip ecaps gnieb ta doog era yehT
.daetsni sIA eht ot meht nialpxe ot yrt dna tis ot evah sgod oS .skcap tej htiw ylf ro miws rehtar dluow yehT
.yhs oot era yeht tub
.das ton era uoy os sgniht nialpxe lliw dna dneirf ruoy eb ot tnaw sgoD .ediug siht ekam ot rehtegot dekrow sgod fo stoL .yako si taht
.meht hcaet ot evah ew dna pu ssem yeht ,semitemoS .etacitsemod ot ysae dna trams yrev era sIA
.llewyraeB yb cisum htiw
.sdneirf ruoy htiw maet a sa gnikrow dna saedi ruoy gnirahs rof doog yrev si gniklaT .klat ot retupmoc laiceps a sesu god A  .taht ekil rehto hcae pleh sdneirF
,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A :tfilpuP“
.sgniht dna sretupmoc dna AND gnisu
,meht rof sliat emos tliub eW .erom nrael ot ecneics emos did eW .sgnileef on evah yeht esuaceb desufnoc teg yeht tub ,sdneirf doog eb ot yrt sIA ehT
.snamuh dellac seiceps a era sdneirf tseb ruO snamuH
.laer era yeht tub ,llems on evah yehT .retupmoc a morf eciov a era yehT
.sterces ruo lla meht llet ew dna sdneirf tseb ruo era snamuh eht esuaceb
:sgel tsewef eht evah yeht ecnis
SDNEIRF RUO & SGOD :ENO RETPAHC
,tah yobwoc a ni god yffulf a,opmeT yb
,thgin ta yllaicepse
,nuK'O epmeT yb ”1 retpahC
YHW :NOITCUDORTNI
.ni dnuora klaw ot stobor meht tliub snamuh ehT .klat nac yeht os sretupmoc laiceps ruo fo emos meht evag eW
.retrams su edam osla yehT
.uoy tep meht gnivah yb
.uoy tep lliw namuh yna tuoba tsuj os meht deniart evah eW
sIA eht esuaceb tespu era snamuh emoS .thgil-naht-retsaf dna ygolonhcetonan ekil skcirt od nac yeht ecnis ,sdneirf retupmoc evah ot ecin si tI
.meht rof llems ot evah ew os ,sllems gnillems ta doog ton era yehT
:ENO RETPAHC FO DNE
,sdneirf ruo lla fo tsewols eht era yeht ,retaw eht fo tuO
noitseuq a uoy dnuora god a ksa ot emit doog a si woN
secnegilletnI laicifitrA
.god a ma I .iH sgoD
.sgniht pu gnikcip dna gnibmilc rof epahs doog a era hcihw
.siht ekil ecneics fo stol od eW
.sgel ruof meht evag ew esuaceb ylbaborp ,snihplod ro snamuh naht retteb klaw ot denrael yehT
.retupmoc a ot tfilpu na gniod yb snamuh eht htiw sIA eht edam eW
!doog yrev si esrevinU ehT .esrevinU ehT ni gnineppah era sgniht fo stoL
,gniklaw ta dab era yeht
.sgniht kaerb yeht os ,hguoht ,gib era yehT .su htiw yalp ot ekil yehT .nuf fo stol era snihploD  !enon
,elbuort esuac netfo yehT
,d'F yllarutluC ta retirw ffats eht si ohw
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,nuK'O epmeT yb ”1 retpahC ,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A
,snamuh eht ekilnU
,sgnileef ro selcsum ro stug on evah sIA eht esuaceB
,desufnoc era uoy fI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.rehto hcae htiw sdneirf emoceb meht pleh ot gniyrt era ew tub ,sIA eht fo deracs llits era snamuh eht fo emoS
,hguoht su depleh snamuh ehT
,rehto hcae tep ot meht teg ot yrt eW
.hguoht ,yako si tI .meht rewop ot sgnileef on evah yeht tub
.meht wohs ton did yeht os
.meht fo duorp yrev era eW
,su ekil decnavda era yeht litnu snamuh eht wohs ot ton meht dlot ew dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.netae teg ton dna doof teg meht depleh dna dluoc ew snamuh-tsomla tsecin eht dnuof eW
:tfilpuP“   yojne esaelP
su deksa sIA ehT
.doog sa saw ti thguoht sIA eht ro snamuh eht rehtien tub ,meht tep ot snamuh emos deksa eW
.hguoht ,doog era yehT !ykoops si tahT
.snamuh naht esrow neve
.sdneirf doog era eW !llew yllaer gniog si tI
.sgniht otni nur ton od uoy os
soediv/QdQdeRxpAVq4xC2v7YA-SZCU/lennahc/moc.ebutuoy.www//:sptth apniJ/llewyraeB :cisuM  sepips/moc.tratnaived.www//:sptth sepiP maS :trA  soediv/dFyllarutluC/c/moc.ebutuoy.www//:sptth d'F yllarutluC :oediv noinapmoC  123opmet/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:sptth nuK'O epmeT :noitarran dna gnitirW  .tnuocca yrruFoS sih ro ytiniffAruF sih no
das ton era sIA ehT
,taht tuoba yppah si ydobyrevE
.meht fo duorp yrev era eW
.ranos nrael ot meht rof trams si ti os ,ees ot thgil fo stol deen snamuH
,das os teg yeht taht das si tI
.sepa erew yeht dna sevlow erew ew nehw sdneirf emaceb eW
.gnol yrev snihplod eht gnitacitsemod neeb ton evah ew
!krow fo tol a si snihplod htiw sdneirf gnieB
.skcirt eseht meht hcaet ton lliw
.meht fo duorp yrev era eW
.ecaps retuo ni mraw gniyats rof ruf kciht dna ni doof gnittup rof ydob a dna trams gnieb rof daeh a dna gniggaw rof liat a dna gninnur rof sgel ruof evah eW .htraE ehT dellac tenalp a morf era eW
.sllems gnitseretni dna wen sah ti esuaceb taerg si esrevinU ehT
si yrots s’yadot dna
.niaga yppah teg yeht tub
,snoitcudorP tenalPruF yb seires dliW sexiS dna llafdniW eht fo retirw eht dna
,snamuh eht htiw sdneirf doog eb ot meht depleh evah eW
ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A :TFILPUP
:kcirt tseb rieht od ro sloot esu ot evah yeht ,teiuq os era yeht esuaceB .nihplod a ekil kaeuqs neve ro krab ro lwoh tonnac yehT
.noitats ecaps a ro esuoheraw a gnieb ekil sboj ta doog yrev era yehT .derob ro derit ro yrgnuh teg ton od yeht
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ecaps dna stenalp dna srats fo edam si hcihw ,esrevinU ehT gnirolpxe era eW
.decnavda yrev era sgoD  .sllems gnillems ta doog yrev era seson ruO
.sdiuqil rehto ro retaw eht erolpxe yeht
,tenalp a ro rats a ot ecneics od ro sdneirf ees og ot tnaw ew nehW
!nwo rieht no lla ti detnevni yehT .gniklat
.sgnileef gnivah ton tuoba
.maet taerg a era ew snaem tahT !sisoibmys a evah eW
,tfilpuP“ saw sihT
.teiuq yrev osla era snamuH
.meht ni teg esaelp ot sIA eht deksa dna seidob tobor tliub eW .ecneics erom emos gniod era ew oS .sdneirf eb sdneirf ruoy gnikam naht reisae si sdneirf gnikaM  .snamuh ot sdneirf retteb meht ekam ot edoc 'sIA eht ot gnixif fo stol od eW .strepxe namuh era eW .sIA ot snamuh nialpxe ot evah ew ,semit fo stoL
,su llet ot ton meht dlot osla eW
.snamuh eht fo emos thguat yehT
.gnisufnoc eb nac ti tuB
.retpahc txen eht ot no eunitnoc ro
,semitemos das teg yehT
.pu meht reehc ot evah ew os
.era sgod ro snamuh naht nwod dna pu tuoba gnikniht ta retteb hcum era snihplod eht ,talf ton si naeco eht esuaceB
.oot htraE ehT morf era yehT
.ranos dellac si kcirt tahT
.neila na ro yppup a ro emit gnol a rof xob a ni nezorf namuh a ro IA wen a era uoY
.sIA dellac era sdneirf tsewen ruO
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
uoy rof daer dna nettirw ”1 retpahC
.sretupmoc dna snihplod dna sepa fo tuo sdneirf edam evah ew ,raf oS .sdneirf gnikam si kcirt tseb ruo tub ,skcirt doog fo stol wonk eW  .snoitats dellac era yeht ,yats yeht esuaceB