,evil ot tnaw ew ecalp fo dnik eht tuoba si ecneics eht nehW
.ecin si htraE ehT
.erehpS lanreB a dellac si ti
.taht od ot yaw tseb eht fo erus ton era yeht tub
,ytivarg fo ytnelp evah yeht esuaceB .tenalP
,skaerb epor eht fI .skcor ecaps dna spihs fo yaw eht fo tuo elggiw lliw taht epor gnorts a deen uoY
.snoitats fo sdnik lla dliub yehT
.ecin eb nac tenalp a no gniviL .ekam ew secalP
.pot a ekil elbbow ot stnaw ti
evah nac uoy nehW
,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A ,tfiL puP .flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,nuK'O epmeT yb 3 retpahC ,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A
.nwod on dna pu hcum oot sah ti ecnis ytivarg on dna
.eloh kcalb a semoceb dna skaerb ti nehT .pu flesti dloh ot hguone gnorts ton si ti dna rehtegot rettam hcum oot tup uoy nehw neppah seloh kcalB .eloH kcalB
.htuom ruoy htiw gniws uoy epor a dna llab a ekil
.suruaT drofnatS ro
.sdneirf rieht eb dna yademos sneila teem ot tnaw eW .tenalp eht no evil sneila on erus yrev era ew fi gnimrofarret od ylno eW .uoy truh dluoc taht ygrene ecaps tuo speek tenalp tengam A .niaga tengam a ti ekam ot tengam a gnieb deppots sah ti fi tenalp eht fo edisni eht tlem ot evah ew semitemoS .no evil ot ecin si ti litnu tenalp a no slamina dna sdees dna stemoc gnippord snaem tI
.tseb eht era sIA ehT .god a ksa ot emit doog a si won
3 retpahc fo dnE
.ti htiw od nac yeht esle tahw ees dna niaga rats a ot ti gnirb thgim yeht ,tuo swaht reve ti fI .dloc eht ekil sretupmoc esuaceb secalp eseht ekil sIA
,edistuo ynihs eb ot elbbub eht llet nac uoy ,thgirb oot si nus eht fI
.selcitrap dna tsud ecaps morf uoy tcetorp ot sreyal evah selbbub ehT
.srats dnuora og stenalP dlroW gniR
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioVehT
.snips dna gib si ti
tfE yllarutluC ta retirw ffats eht si ohw
,tunod laer a ekilnU
.meht no sgniht dliub dna meht dnif sIA neht tub ,meht esol sratS .semitemos stenalp htiw sneppah tahT .ti sdnif ydobemos yademos neht tub llab a sesol god a semitemoS .tenalP eugoR
.llewyrraB yb cisum dna
.sneila tuohtiw stenalp erom dnif syawla nac ew os ,gib si esrevinu ehT .das meht ekam tsuj ebyam ro meht truh dluoc tenalp rieht gnignahC
seires dliW sexiS dna llafdniW
gnir gib a gnikam era sIA eht ,stenalp fo stol gnikam fo daetsni tuB
.srats naht reggib neve era emoS
.slatibro sknaB dellac sdlrow gnir elttil gnikam osla era yehT
.no dnuora nur dna no dnal nac ew meht fo emos
.gib era taht sgniht fo stol tuoba deklat evah eW
.emit dna ytivarg fo esuaceb ti teg tonnac uoy esuaceb ,kcab tnaw uoy eloh kcalb a ni gnihtyna tup ton dluohs uoY
,hguoht rettam fo stol fo edam era stenalP
,gniht gib a tuoba noitseuq a evah uoy fI
.emils laiceps a htiw pu slaes ti
.spihs rof secalp emos evael ot evah uoy os ,elbbub eht ni pihs a dnal tonnac uoY
.snoitacilbuP tenalP riaF yb
.enihsnus htiw mraw stunod eht peek srorriM ykS
.tenalP gnimrofarreT
.no evil ot ysae si tI
.dloc yrev era yeht os ,enihsnus on evah stenalp esehT
eht fo retirw eht dna
.seloh kcalb ni llef sgniht emos tub ,sgniht fo stol sah esrevinu ehT
.evil ew secalp fo sepyt emos era ereH
.tnaiG saG nedraG
.ykcits ti edam revetahw pu naelc dna ti teg ot pom a semitemos dna kcaptej a htiw pu og ot evah uoy nehT
tfahs rotavele na sah ebut eht fo elddim ehT
.noitats ecaps a dliub ot emit doog a si tahT .su rof ydaer ton si taht tenalp a yb evil ot tnaw ew hguoht semitemoS
,llab a otni pu spmul taht rettam era stenalP .stenalp si gnitseretni tsom eht tub ,siht od nac srats rehto dna sag dna skcoR .meht dnuora gniog sgniht evah yllausu srats
ecalp taht dliub nac ew
.edisni rekrad eb lliw elbbub eht dna
.sgniht dna spihs dna tenalp eht ees dna ti edir uoy elihw wodniw eht tuo kool nac uoY
sepipmaS yb tra htiw
niarB akhsoirtaM
.wons ekil sllaf dna dilos sezeerf ria ehT
,seton wohs eht ni dnif nac uoy oediv noinapmoc sah yrots siH
.avon a dellac si tahT .sedolpxe ti fi rettam fo sepyt wen fo hcnub a pu skooc osla tI .ytterp si ti yawa raf yrev morf tub ,toh dna thgirb yrev si tI
.ecioVehT ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.elbbub a ni ti peek dna ria emos gnirb nac uoY
,emit a ta ecalp eno ni ylno si tenalp a esuaceB
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.srobhgien erom evah nac uoy nehT
tah yobwoc a ni god yffulf a
.won meht fo emos tuoba klat lliw eW .esrevinu eht edisni tif sgniht gib yllaer fo stoL
si yrots s'yadot dna
.yzoc era stenalp emoS .ynoloC
reloopS dna eloH kcalB
.ees ot ereht evil neht dna
.rednilyC llieN'O
.tnuocca yriafliS sih ro
.bahX na dellac si sihT
.ecneics od ew oS
,tunod laer a ekiL .ytic tunod a sa noitats ecaps ruoy dliub ot si nwod dna pu emos ekam ot yaw rehtonA
.emit emas eht ta edolpmi dna edolpxe lliw ti ,rehtegot steg rettam fo stol dna stol fI .ratS
.noitats ecaps a dliub ot reisae si ti os
,tfiL puP saw sihT
.esle erehwemos etag rehtona tuo emoc dna elohmrow a ni og lliw uoy ,meht ni pihs a ylf uoy fI
.ynoloc a dellac si ti ,tenalp a no rehtegot evil ot trats elpoep nehW .ecin si tI
.stunod eht kcats neve nac uoY
.epor a no nwod ro pu uoy sekat taht ni dnats uoy xob a si rotavele nA rotavelE ecapS
.krow fo tol a tub
.ria on evah stenalp emoS .emodoiB
.revo dna revo secalp emas eht ot og ot tnaw ew semitemoS etaG elohmroW
.stunod era sepyt eht fo lla tuB
,noitats gninnips ruoy fo epahs eht rettam oN
.yticirtcele otni ti nrut dna thgil sti pu kaos yehT .rats a dnuora slenap ralos fo stol tup
,elbbub eht ni eloh a ekop uoy fI
.selbbub reggib emos otni selbbub eht nrut ebyam dna tenalp a fo strap gib revoc nac uoy ,selbbub hguone teg uoy fI .elbbub a ni evil nac uoy nehT
.yaw rehto eht nips ti gnivah dna dne eht no noitats ecaps rehtona gnittup yb siht xif nac uoY
.rats wen a ekam nac tahT
.kcuts teg dna tfahs rotavele eht tih nac ti ,ykcits si gnihtemos eht fi yllaicepse
.llewyrraB yb cisum htiw
.ni ehtaerb uoy tel ot senihcamonan laiceps sah retaw eht nevE .uoy gnitruh fo daetsni ecaf ruoy fo epahs eht ni tned a teg dluow ti
.selppa fo stol worg stenalp eseht esuaceb ,hguoht yako si tI .ytivarg eht lla fo esuaceb ecuaselppa otni sehsiuqs tI .eroc tenalp eht otni sllaf ti ,ti hctac ton od uoy dna ti gnikcip elihw elppa na spord namuh a fI .stiurf rehto dna selppa worg seert ehT .neerg kool meht ekam sevael eht fo llA .meht no seert gniylf tnalp ew os ,meht no evil tonnac eW .sag era stenalp emoS
.gnimrofarret a si sihT
,eseht fo sepyt laiceps rof seman fo stol evah snamuh ehT
,ebut a fo daetsni llab a si siht ekil ecalp a nehW
,tfiL puP !yojne esaelP
.ereh noitseuq ruoy dnes thgim yeht ,drah yrev kniht ot sIA ksa uoy fI
.stenalp no evil sdneirf ruo fo stoL
nap gniyrf a ekil gnirb uoy sgniht nevE .elcihev ruoy gnihsams morf peek ot pu kaerb lliw ti ,kcor a otni hsarc uoy fI .llaf uoy fi uoy ecnuob lliw dnuorg ehT .ti ni senihcamonan sah rettam eht fo lla erehw noom a si meht fo enO .tseb ekil ew yas ew tahw no desab eseht gnikam era sIA ehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
.emit hcum oot evah reve uoy fi lufesu era yeht os ,edisni emit hcum yrev evah ton od seloh kcalb oslA .rettam erom deen reve uoy fi rettam fo sdnik lla teg dluoc yehT
.yks eht ni ecin kool srats eht ecnis yllaicepse ,sIA eht htiw eerga eW
.sgniht dna taeh dna ria thgir eht evah yehT
.ot ecneics od dluohs ew sgniht rof llems dna meht erolpxe ew woh si tahT
semitemos sIA mrawS nosyD
.tneinevnoc era dna regnol nrub srats elttiL .srats erom deen ew kniht sIA ehT poocS nuS
.dnal ot stej elttil esu lliw xob eht nehT
.meht no evil dna meht no sesuoh tup eW
sIA ehT serutcurtS ageM
.edisni ffuts eht esu dna seloh kcalb trapa ekat ot gniyrt era sIA ehT
.sdneirf ruo tisiv nac ew os no evil ew stenalp yb meht tup sIA ehT
.egufeR tnecsA na ekil ebut eht ot desserp teg lliw uoy os
noitatS ecapS leehW gnitatoR
,ecaf eht ni uoy tih dna flehs a ffo llef ti fi oS .senihcamonan teg lliw
.drah yrev krow
,gnigniws si ti esuaceb ecaps ni syats pot eht dna gnol yrev si epor ehT .hguoht secalp owt uoy sekat ylno tI
,noitats ecaps ruoy rof nwod a dna pu na ekam ot tnaw uoy fI
,opmeT yb uoy rof daer dna nettirw ,3 retpahc
.snootrac fo meht sdnimer ereht gnitisiv esuaceb nooM nooT a bahX siht llac snamuh ehT .serutnevda htiw osla tub doof htiw yllaicepsE .ekil yllaer yeht dneirf gnitisiv a ekil uoy taert lliw dna snamuh ekil erom tca sIA esehT .segde prahs on dna seidob tfos dna sllems ecin dna seye gib evah yehT .yracs eb ot ton dengised era dna ereht evil seidob htiw sIA laicepS
.ebut gib a sa ti dliub ot si yaw eno
.meht no krow ew os ,ton era stenalp tsoM
.sgnihT dnuoR egraL rehtO dna stenalP
.ecaps ni setag gib gnikam yb taht od su pleh sIA ehT
.tatibaH latnemirepxE
.enoemos truh ton seod ti os dnuorg eht edisni pu loops lliw ti
,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A ,tfiL puP
leehW nuarB noV ekil
.dnuorg eht ni kcuts si mottob ehT
.ebut eht ni dnuora klaw nac uoY
.rof ksa ot tahw wonk ot drah si ti ,gnihtyna
.yaw eht ni teg ton dna ti wollof dluoc stenalp fo stol
,nuK'O epmeT yb 3 retpahC
.edisni ria yltsom htiw gnir a si ti
,sdneirf ruo eb ot tnaw sIA ehT
.edisni eht no snaeco dna ssarg dna seert htiw
.sgoD nahT reggiB sgnihT ,3 retpahC
,aedi doog yrev a si tI
.su ekil ot sneila eht tnaw eW .sesuoh dliub ew erofeb sneila rof kcehc syawla eW
.lufthguoht yrev si tahT
.erus ton era sgod nevE
.selohmrow ro stengam htiw skrow taht poocs gib a gnidliub era yehT
.srats eht deen ew dna ,yssem era savon esuaceB .savon od ton dluohs ew yas sIA ehT .savon od srats emos ekam ot tnaw semitemos snamuh ehT
,tsaf ytterp snips ebut ehT
,drah oot gnihtemos worht uoy fI
.sretupmoc fo stol rewop ot ygrene eht esu nac yeht os srats dnuora selbbub gib gnidliub era yeht ,sretupmoc ni evil yeht ecniS .tol a kniht sIA ehT
.ytivarg fo esuaceb nwod dna pu na evah ylno stenalP .ytaolf si ecapS
ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dnA
.meht ksa uoy fi yticirtcele uoy evig lliw yehT .setag elohmrow ni selohmrow eht gnittup ro stenalp gnimrofarret ekil ,sgniht od ot ti esu yehT
.sretupmoc htiw lla sreyal evah selbbub ehT
.esle erehwemos ti tup dna rats eht fo emos pu poocs ot tnaw yehT
.rats a dellac si tahT
.stenalp fo sepyt laiceps emos era ereH
.ecaps ot uoy sekat dna llat yrev si rotavele ecaps A