.tiusecaps a raew nac uoy
,og ot ecalp ecin yrev a si tI
.daetsni emit nuf a evah ot dna
.aelf dellac si seiceps gub rehtonA
,ton era emos tub
.dlog tsuj era yeht os
,htam ot gnidroccA
secalp wen ot
.ecaps ot og uoy erofeb slamina suoregnad rof pihsecaps ruoy llems syawlA
- ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A
!dliw llits si ti tub ,ecin si tI
.llewyraeB yb cisum dna
drah yrev devlove meht fo emos dna
,elttil a doolb ruoy sknird ylno eno hcaE
- ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A :tfilpuP“ saw sihT
,noisrev oediv a yb deinapmoccA
.uoy ni nixot tup ot tuo seilf taht hsifyllej eht fo eceip elttil a tsycotamen A .stsycotamen htiw uoy bats lliw yeht esuaceb
.ittefnoc ekil llams
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,nuK'O epmeT yb
htraE ehT no evil smreg fo stoL .smreg ekil ,sraeb naht rellams hcum era meht fo emoS !reikaens neve era htraE
,selcitrap htiw meht toohs ot
.rohtua eht yb daeR
.oidar a no eno eht ekil ,rekaeps a morf ti yalp ot deen lliw uoY
.skcor suoregnad fo edam osla era htraE ehT fo straP  .ytefas
,pihs ro noitats ecaps a no
,yarps gub eht gnirb ot togrof uoy fI
yhcti era sgub fo stol morf setib ehT
,stenalp demrofarret nO
.sraeb yb netae teg ton lliw uoy
.uoy ni smreg efas-ton tup nac yeht tub
,god.ecioveht ta
.llewyraeB yb cisum htiw
.rats a otni ylf ot ton swonk ydobyrevE
.revo lla grobyc a era uoy esuaceb niks latem evah uoy fi ti knird tonnac tub
.otiuqsom eht dellac gub rotaderp gniknird-doolb a si
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,htraE ehT tuoba klat lliw ew ,yadoT
”esrevinU eht ni ecalP suoregnaD tsoM ehT
,tenalp ruoy no skcor dab fo stol evah uoy fI
.rood pihsecaps eht esolc neht
,noitats ecaps a fo roolf eht no sllaf ekac fI
.ruf ruoy ni ton era yeht os
”yarps gub eht“ dellac
.dnuora og nac uoy os
.tnuocca yrruFoS sih ro ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,kcor wen a ees uoy fI
meht ta krab ew ,ereht sraeb era ereht fI
su htiw sgniht ecin eht ekat ot drah yrev dekrow elpoep fo stoL
,d'F yllarutluC ta retirw ffats eht si ohw ,nuK'O epmeT yb
!trams os era yehT
,yako era skcor tsoM
ton dna stnalp eht lla no wehc nac uoy ,tenalp demrofarret a nO
ti nacs ot rosiv ruoy esu nac uoy
.htraE ehT dellac tenalp a si ecaps ni ecalp suoregnad tsom ehT
kcis uoy ekam tonnac yeht tuB .kcis su ekam ot
htraE ehT no lamina suoregnad tsom eht
sgniht efas-ton eht evael ot dna
ehT no dnuorg eht no sllaf ekac fI
rennacs a esu dluohs uoy ,htraE
rewohs a ekat dluohs uoy tub
noitats a ro pihs a no era uoy nehW  .ereht
.htraE ehT no tuoba luferac eb dluohs uoy sgniht eht fo emos era esehT
,snoitcudorP tenalPruF yb
tnalp htraE si tahT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.oot efas ton era stnalp emos tub
,tenalp demrofarret a ro
- ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A
!toh oot era yehT
,skcor esoht yawa tup dna seloh gid ew
syas rennacs eht fI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
pihsecaps ruoy no srenaelc-ria ehT
.enoemos truh ton od yeht os
si dna ria eht hguorht seilf tI
.ekac taht tae ot efas si ti
.su rof efas eb dluow ti kniht dluow uoy os
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
esrevinU ehT nI ecalP suoregnaD tsoM ehT
,ereht neeb ydaerla sah ohw enoemos htiw og dluohs uoy ,ereht neeb reven evah uoy fi tub
.xob a ni ti peek ot evah uoy
,ti no devlove snamuh dna snihplod dna sgoD
.saelf sedolpxe taht dnuos rehtona evah snihplod ehT
.aval ro cinesra ekil
.naeco eht ni evil taht sbolb ylggiw era hsifylleJ
.dewehc eb ton dluohs stnalp eht fo emos ,htraE ehT nO
,ekac eht tuoba ”detceteD snegohtaP :regnaD“
.yawa meht peek ot
sIA eht ksa nac uoy
.sotiuqsom sedolpxe taht
:tfilpuP“   yojne esaelP
llems laiceps a esu semitemos eW
detnevni snihplod eht dnuos laiceps eht esu ot si sgub morf flesruoy tcetorp ot yaw tseb eht tuB
:tfilpuP“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
sraeb rof llems ot luferac yrev neeb evah sgod esuaceb si tahT
.gnitlem ro nosiop si ti fi ees ot
eid ton ot uoy pleh nac yeht os ,ereht sevil ro
”esrevinU eht ni ecalP suoregnaD tsoM ehT
.efas ton era esrevinU eht ni secalp emoS
.smreg evah ebyam dna
llafdniW eht fo retirw eht dna
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,htraE ehT otno kcab og meht ekam ot
.sraeb on sah ecaps yhw si tahT
.morf efas eb ot ysae era meht fo tsoM
,tah yobwoc a ni god yffulf
,yawa raf yrev morf meht ees uoy dnA
!tsaf poh yeht tub ,ylf tonnac yehT
,sgub eht pu kcus lliw
.ekac taht tae uoy erofeb ti no
).hguoht ,truh thgim stug dna htuom ruoY( .eid
,doolb ruoy knird ot warts prahs a sah tI
.ytefas erom rof ,emoh teg uoy nehw swap ruoy hsaw ebyam dna
seires dliW sexiS dna
yawa yats dluohs uoy nehT
sepiP maS yb tra htiw
,sregnad lamina eht fo emos era esehT
ehT no smrofefil emos tub
,ykaens tib elttil a era sraeB
aval ro cinesra ro dael tnaw uoy fI
.htraE ehT tisiv ew nehw spihsecaps ruo no gnitteg
.ekac taht tae ton dluohs uoy neht
.wolg semitemos dna ytterp era yehT
”esrevinU eht ni ecalP suoregnaD tsoM ehT
.uoy edisni teg ton od yeht fi
meht hcuot ton dluohs uoy tuB
a,opmeT yb uoy rof daer dna nettirw