,reyrd riah a htiw ro
!erahs nac ew snaem tI
llams era skroF .snikpan dna skrof
”5 retpahC ,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A
.yad eht fo trap rof boj ruoy od uoy ,syad tsoM boJ
.melborp eht evlos pleh lliw dna ecneics dneirf decnavda yrev evah sgoD
stsalb taht enihcam duol a si hcihw
.sgniht pord meht ekam ro revo meht pit thgim uoy ,esiwrehtO
.kcirt tnatropmi na era srennaM .sdneirf eb ot snaem ti tahw si tahT .sdneirf evah ot ecin eb ot evah uoY .tnatropmi si ti tuB .tespu ro derit ro yrgnuh era uoy fi ,ecin eb ot tluciffid eb nac tI .retupmoc a ro
.meht eltrats ton od uoy os ,tsrif ereht era uoy wonk yeht erus ekam tsuJ
.ecin eb ot tpecxe nosaer on rof yltneg meht hcuot uoy nehw si gnitteP
.nepo llits si taht eye
.srennam elbat decnavda yrev evah snamuH
.meht tep ot ro uoy tep enoemos evah ot si eldduc ot yaw tnatropmi rehtonA
.eeffoc knird ton od sgoD
.gnipeels dellac gniht a od htraE ehT morf elpoep lacigoloiB PEELSA
.uoy rof kool og dna tsol era uoy kniht lliw yeht ,esiwrehtO
.tsafkaerb emos uoy tnirp ot nehctik eht llet nac uoY
.doof ekam skooc erehw ecalp a si tnaruatser A .tnaruatser a ot og nac uoy ,kooc tonnac nehctik ruoy dna uoy doof a tnaw uoy fI
.stsacdop ruoy
.sgrobyc ot ecin eb ot woh wonk ton did ew ,sgrobyc erew elpoep erofeB .srennam retteb ekam ew woh si tahT
.sdiuqs dna hsif tae yltsom snihploD
.hcuot uoy os uoy ot txen dneirf a evah ot si tespu era uoy fi retteb leef ot yaw tnatropmi rehtonA   .noitatidem si tahT .nwod mlac ot sgniht tuoba kniht dna tis nac nosrep eht ,sneppah taht fI
,eeffoc ekil osla snihploD
.ekawa era uoy ,yad eht fo tsoM EKAWA   .meht
.das si enoemos nehw rof ecitcarp doog si ti dnA .das gnitteg morf enoyreve peek
,hguoht ,esle enoemos no ro
,noitanicullah a si maerd A
.evil uoy sa meht nrael lliw uoY
.sehcneb ro sriahc namuh no tis sgod evah stnaruatser tsoM
gnignis rieht gnicitcarp ro
,snoitcudorP tenalPruF yb seires dliW sexiS dna llafdniW eht fo retirw eht dna
EVIF RETPAHC FO DNE
,depoleved neeb evah seldduc fo sdnik ynaM
.hguoht ,neppah nac sgniht erom stoL
.no retal tae uoy nehw si renniD .yad eht fo elddim eht ni tae uoy nehw si hcnuL
.slwob dna spuc morf gniknird ta dab era yeht tub
.esirnus a fo uoy dnimer ot rethgirb sthgil eht sekam osla ppa repleh ehT
.tisiv yeht nehw meht ot og ylno nac uoy os ,spihs era stnaruatser emoS .sgnidliub era stnaruatser tsoM
apniJ/llewyraeB yb cisum
.elbat a ta elpoep rehto htiw tae uoy nehw rof selur laiceps evah eW   .derit teg ton od sgel tobor rieht esuaceb elbat eht yb dnats tsuj ,hguoht ,snihploD
.srennam grobyc ekam ot ecneics desu eW .od ew woN
.eno sah esuoh yrevE .kniht niarb ruoy pleh ot moor a si seigolonhcet tseb ruo fo enO rewohS
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta
.ecaps erolpxe nac uoy dna suoiciled artxe si doof ehT
.worg niarb ruoy spleh dna ecin sleef nuF .nuf si taht
.skcirt wen nrael meht spleh tI
ekil sloot evah yehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,d'F yllarutluC morf oediv noinapmoc a yb deinapmoccA
,snips taht tenalp a no pu werg seiceps ruo esuaceB
spleh dna dneirf rieht era uoy elpoep sdnimer tI
,smra evah ton od uoy fI
.uoy ot gniklat ro uoy gnittep sdneirf ekil
.ti fo tol a knard ew fi kcis teg dluoc ew os
.snamuh ot tnatropmi yrev htob era yehT
,tah yobwoc a ni god yffulf
.emit a ta elttil a peels artxe
.hguoht ,ragus dna klim woc eht evah nac uoY
.sgniht esoht etsat dna ,leef ,raeh ,ees neve dna ereht ton era taht sllems llems uoY
.yhs eb ot yako si tI .kcab ro sredluohs eht no tpecxe ,rehto hcae tep ot yhs oot netfo era snamuh tludA
.yad a ni neppah ylbaborp taht sgniht emos tuoba deklat eW
.niarb rieht fo sevlah htob htiw peels lamron od yeht nehw rof smaerd rieht pu evas yehT
,ssel elttil a peels snihplod dna snamuH
.sterces tsomla era emoS .suoivbo era emoS .srennam fo stol sah yteicoS
.sgniht kaerb yeht dna ytegdif dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
!htab tnenamrep a ekil si tahT .naeco
elbaticxe oot meht sekam tI
!maet a era uoy ,rehtegoT
.llewyraeB yb cisum htiw
.lamron si ti tub
.pihs a gnireets era uoy nehw maerd ton dluohs uoY
.noitisop yfmoc a ni yats ot swollip dna mraw su peek ot steknalb esu eW
,nikpan gib a si hcihw
.emas eht si ti esiwrehto tub ,tnalp eeffoc a fo sdees fo daetsni tnalp aet a fo sevael htiw edam si tI
.sgod sa sdoof emas eht tae nac snamuh ,yltsoM
,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A :tfilpuP“
.buthtab a dellac si sihT
.ekacnap taht tae thgim nihplod a ,naeco eht no ti taolf dna hsif fo tuo ekacnap a ekam uoy fI
,IA na era uoy fI
,gnos a raeh ro koob a daer ro sdneirf ruoy htiw emag a yalp uoy nehW nuF
.yad yreve peels fo sruoh net tuoba deen sgoD .kcis gnitteg morf peek dna worg dna laeh su spleh tI
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
rewohs a dellac si tI
.ria toh htiw uoy
.ti od ot meht tnaw ew os yppah meht sekam ti tub ,retaw tnalp no yteicos ruoy esab ot yllis elttil a si tI
.rettam tnalp deird fo selgnatcer era snikpaN
,nuK'O epmeT yb 5 retpahC
.hceeps a gnicitcarp ro
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
dellac selur wollof uoy ,elpoep htiw dna ekawa era uoy nehW srennaM
.kooc ew tahw ekil yeht semitemos tub ,kooc yllausu ton od snihploD
.ytrid era uoy fi uoy snaelc osla tI
.ygolonhcet emas eht yllacisab si tI
sthguoht tnatropmi gnikniht eb thgim yehT
.ti ni ragus dna klim woc ekil sgniht tup yehT
.emit eht lla ekawa era uoy
.elpoep ot dneirf doog a gnieb snaem tahT .ecin gnieb si yad a ni od uoy gniht tnatropmi tsom ehT eciN gnieB
eht ni era yeht fi rewohs ot deen ton od snihploD
!detnelat yrev si tahT
eht ni evil snihplod tsoM
,stenalp fo snaeco
,pan etadpu na gnikat IA na ees uoy fI
.steprac ro safos ro sdeb ekil
.ydob ruoy fo erutarepmet eht tuoba si tI .uoy no retaw mraw syarps dna
.skrof esu ton od sgod dna snihplod fi dnatsrednu lliw snamuH
.uoy rof lwob a ni ti stup dna tnaw uoy tahw sekam tI
lamina na era uoy hguoht neve ,elpoep ot ecin era uoy nehw era srennaM .srennam
.rehto hcae raen peels eW
.tew yrev teg ylbaborp lliw uoy ,meht tisiv uoy fI .retaw eht ni yawflah era taht sesuoh evah yehT .spihsecaps no ro noitats ecaps a dnuora yaw eht lla og taht sloop gib ni evil emos tub
,ilumits eciton dna suoicsnoc era uoy snaem sihT
,emit eht lla boj ruoy od ot evah ton od uoY
renniD dna hcnuL
.maerd semitemos uoy ,peels uoy nehW maerD
.ni yal ot uoy rof retaw fo loop a hctac nac srewohs emoS
:tfilpuP“yojne esaelP
teg ew ,hguoht ,semitemoS
.enola eb meht tel yllausu dluohs uoy ,rewohs eht ni si enoemos fI   .ecin sleef ti esuaceb yawyna od yeht semitemos tuB
tuoba klat lliw eW
.llab eeffoc eht tae yeht dna retaw eht ni ti pord uoy nehT
.eldduc a dellac si sihT
,tfilpuP“ saw sihT
.emoh rieht ni gnivil namuh eno tsael ta evah sgod tsoM
.tnalp eeffoc a fo sdees eht gnikooc yb llems ecin a sesaeler tI
,rewohs eht ni enod era uoy nehW .sgniht esoht od uoy spleh rewohs A
,neppah thgim taht gnihtemos tuoba snoitseuq evah uoy fI
seldduC dna noitatideM
eht htiw skcor ecaps rof tuo hctaw dna peels teg nac yeht nehT
.doog si tahT .hguoht ,yaw siht maerd ton od yehT
.eeffoc fo daetsni aet knird sdneirf ruo fo emoS
.yrgnuh eb lliw uoy pu ekaw uoy nehw os ,gnipeels era uoy elihw tae ton od uoY tsafkaerB
.enoemos dnuora smra ruoy parw uoy erehw ,guh a ekil
nuK'O epmeT yb
.htnom elohw a rof pu yats lliw snihplod ,semitemoS .etal pu yats ot ekil yehT .hguone peels ot snihplod dna snamuh eht teg ot yrt eW   .buthtab eht ni peels ot ekil snihplod emoS .elpoep ro sgniht otni gnimmiws-peels morf meht speek tI .retaw eht ni skcommah ni peels snihploD
a,opmeT yb uoy rof daer dna nettirw ”5 retpahC
,eeffoc nihplod a evig oT
.riahc a no gnittis elihw tae yllausu yeht os
.esle erehwyna ton dna htuom ruoy ni doof nwo ruoy gnitteg tuoba era yeht ,yltsoM .srennam elbat eht dellac era yehT
.noitazilivic ni evil ot ecin si tI
tuoba deen llits yeht tub
.ti tae uoy nehT
.ypmurg meht sekam tahT
,oot snamuh naht rellams era sgod tsoM
,d'F yllarutluC ta retirw ffats eht si ohw
.ssem llams a pu naelc ot snikpan esu uoY
.meht detacitsemod ew yhw fo trap si sihT
ecaf ruoy no doof teg uoy fI
uoy fo tser eht no ro
.hsif a meht gnirb ebyam dna ynapmoc meht peek dna meht ot klat dluohs uoy os ,siht od yeht nehw derob teg od yehT
.no gniog si tahw wonk yeht os ,ti od uoy erofeb yako si ti erus ekam dluohs uoY
,lewot a htiw ffo yrd uoy
.rohtuA eht yb daeR
.rotcod a llac nac yeht os enoemos llet esaelp ,eeffoc fo tol a knard uoy dna god a era uoy fI
.peelsa dna ekawa otni emit pu kaerb ew ,ecaps ni nevE .sthgin dna syad evah ot ekil sniarb ruo
.edoc ton era uoy esuaceb ,edisni tif ot elba eb ton thgim uoy ,meht tisiv uoy fI .ecaps ni neve ,erehwyna
,roolf eht ffo tae ot llat oot era snamuH
.yhtlaeh yats uoy os nuf evah dluohs uoY
.evil uoy ecalp eht si emoh A emoH
.ypeels eb ot tegrof ot sniarb rieht sllet eeffoC
.noitazilivic dellac si ti ,rehto hcae ot ecin eb ot rehtegot krow elpoep fo stol nehW
!erofeb deneppah reven evah taht neppah lliw sgniht emoS
.tleb rebbarg ruoy gnisu nikpan a htiw ffo ti epiw dluohs uoy
dna sepiP maS yb tra htiw
.ti knird ot ekil snamuH
.meht ot klat ot niaga ekawa era yeht litnu tiaw ot evah lliw uoy
ekam ot sgge dna stiurf dna sniarg dna taeh sesu tI
.pu ekaw ot uoy dnimer ot peelsa llits era uoy elihw no ti snrut ppa repleh ruoY
.yad eht gnirud ekawa eb ot ekil elpoep tsoM
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sruoh dna sruoh rof peels dluoc uoy taht derit os ton tub
.htuom ruoy ni doof gnittup rof sraeps
.dneirf a yb yal tsuj ot doog osla si tI .tleb rebbarg a htiw enoemos guh nac uoy
.meht ekil uoy swonk nosrep eht taht si gniht tnatropmi ehT
.enihcam eeffoc a dellac pu su ekaw ot loot laiceps a evah eW eeffoC
.saedi fo kniht ot dna pleh ot ereh era uoy esuaceb erom neve od nac eW .ereh era uoy doog si ti snaem tahT
.egdirrop ro selffaw ro stunod ro settelemo
,derit leef uoy fi doog era spaN
.sruoh ruof-ytnewt yreve htob od dluohs uoY
.yad eht rof pu uoy srewop ti esuaceb tnatropmi si tsafkaerb A
,secived tfos no peels ot ekil sgod dna snamuH   .tespu dna
derit eb lliw uoy ,hguone peels ton od uoy fI .sruoh thgie
.god a ksa nac uoy ,ti gnirud ecin eb ot woh erus ton era uoy dna melborp a otni nur uoy fI
.meht tuoba yrrow ton od tub ,dab ro doog eb nac smaerD
.noitacav a no era uoy fi maet ruoy llet dluohs uoy tub
.sdneirf ruo dnuora eb ot ecin si ti esuaceb ti od tsuj ew won tub
.srennam ot ecneics od ew ,semitemoS
.emit a ta niarb rieht flah htiw peels ylno yeht ,spihs gnitolip era snihplod nehW
YAD A EVIF RETPAHC
.semitemos span ekat sIA
.tespu leef uoy ,semitemoS
.ni sdees eht skooc ti retaw eht serutpac enihcam eeffoc A
.oot doog si tahT !yppah era uoy nehw eldduc osla nac uoY
.rettib oot si tI
.tespu sleef dneirf a rO
.sevlesruo yb dluoc ew naht rehtegot gnikrow erom od nac elpoep esuaceb sboj od eW
.kcab eht no enoyna tuoba tsuj tep nac uoY
.sredluohs ro kcab ro daeh eht no snamuh gnuoy dna snihplod dna sgod tep nac uoY
.nuf fo sdnik wen revocsid ot esrevinU ehT gnirolpxe era eW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sdneirf ruoy htiw tnaruatser a ot og ot ecin si tI
.gniht taht tuoba god a ksa ot emit doog a si won
.pu sllif ylwols taht rab gnidaol a uoy wohs lliw neercs rieht esuaceb gnineppah si siht llet nac uoY
.uoy htiw boj ruoy od ylbaborp elpoep rehtO
.stser niarb ruoy woh tsuj era yehT
.leg eagla fo llab a ni ti tup ot evah uoy
.edoc wen htiw niaga no neht dna ffo nrut yehT .setadpu dellac era yehT
,sregit tuoba meht nraw dluoc ew os eb ot desu sihT
.ecno ta lla sneppah peels tsoM paN
evil nac yeht snaem tahT .sretupmoc era semoh IA
.eeffoc hcum oot snihplod ro snamuh eht evig ot ton yrt eW
.tnuocca yrruFoS sih ro ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.uoy dnuora no gniog si tahw fo ssel eciton uoy nehw tser peed a si tI