a,opmeT yb uoy rof daer dna nettirw ”4 retpahC
no gniog si tahw tuo serugif evitceted A
.ti rewsna ot pleh lliw
sepiP maS yb tra htiw
.sllems gnitseretni llems dna doof doog tae ot erus ekam dluohs uoY .sdneirf ruoy ees dna emoh yats thgim uoY
.ti ta doog teg uoy ,ecitcarp uoy sA
.otni kniht yeht stemleh laiceps htiw semitemos dna slortnoc htiw reets stoliP
,snoitcudorP tenalPruF yb
,syad wef a naht erom rof boj rehtona gniod pots uoy fI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.llew yllaer gniod ydaerla era uoy os ,ediug siht gnidnatsrednu
.srepleh evah yeht yhw si tahT
.AND flow fo hcnub a tsuj si god A .yako si taht
,dlo ro kcis ro truh teg uoy fI rotcoD
!scinopordyh dellac si tahT
.sgniht ytterp ees dna secalp tnereffid ot levart thgim uoY
.won sboj emos tuoba klat lliw eW
.trams os era yehT
.sgnileef emas rieht leef stsitra meht swohs ti esuaceb sgniht esoht ekil elpoep rehtO .sgnos gnis dna sgnitniap tniap yehT
apniJ/llewyraeB yb cisum dna
:tfilpuP“yojne esaelP
,tuo derugif evah ew skcirt doog eht lla fo esuaceb si sihT
.aedi taht tset neht ,ti tuoba aedi na htiw pu emoc neht ,melborp a tuoba kniht stsitneicS .ecneics od ew ,erom nrael oT
.atad dna sgnidrocer fo stol ekam uoY .ti tuoba nrael ot lausunu si taht gnihtyna ot ecneics od uoy ,ereht era uoy elihW
,d'F yllarutluC morf oediv noinapmoc a yb deinapmoccA
.stsipareht dellac era elpoep esehT
.ti fo tsom ot neeb ton evah eW
.uoy pleh emoc lliw meht fo eno dna sIA eht ksa nac uoy ,eno deen uoy fI
.pihs a ni ecaps dnuora ylf ro
seulc rof gnikool yb
.tneduts a gnieb yb boj wen a nrael nac uoY
”4 retpahC ,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A
.ecneics taht did yeht woh dnatsrednu lliw sdneirf rieht ,yaw tahT
sgniht xif osla sreenignE
.yretsym a dellac si tahT .gnissim si nosrep a ro tcejbo na fi ekil ,gnineppah si tahw tuoba desufnoc si enoyreve ,semitemoS evitceteD
.rohtuA eht yb daeR
!sisoibmys ruo fo trap si tI
.retupmoc a ot sepahs kaeuqs nac yeht esuaceb sreenigne era snihplod fo stoL
.epahs doog ni niarb ruoy peek uoy os semitemos tsipareht a ot klat dluohs uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
sih ro ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.yssem si trid ecnis
.deewaes worg retaw eht ni smraF
.doof gnipoocs dna gnirrits rof doog era hcihw
.noitacav a no era uoy
.gib yrev si esrevinU ehT rerolpxE
.tneduts a era uoy
.seert ro selbategev ro stiurf ro sniarg worg thgim dnal eht no smraF
.rehto hcae pleh ot woh dna
.hsarc thgim uoy ro nwod dna pu tuoba gnikniht ta doog yrev eb ot evah uoY
SBOJ :RUOF RETPAHC
.gnirolpxe dellac si secalp wen ot gnioG
.sevlow eb tsuj dluow ew ,sevlow htiw pu werg ew fI
.ti ekil thgim uoY .dluohs uoy
,ecapS ot ediuG s'goD A :tfilpuP“
.stsipareht era sgod ynaM
.dlihc eht fo erac ekat pleh ohw tnerap eht fo sdneirf era yehT .stnerapolla dellac era srepleh esehT
.nerdlihc nihplod dna namuh era oS .stneduts era seippup llA
,sllems era seulc fo stoL
yteicos trams a ni pu werg ew ,daetsnI
.enoemos pleh ot si boj esohw enoemos si reltub A reltuB
.yteicos ni evil nac yeht os stol dna stol nrael ot evah nerdlihC
.krow sgnileef dna sniarb woh ta strepxe era elpoep emoS
,nuK'O epmeT yb 4 retpahC
.sdneirf doog eb nac ew nehT
.stnerapolla sa nerdlihc s'rehto hcae fo erac ekat pleh dna rehtegot evil netfo sgod dna snamuH
.tser a deen uoy ,semitemoS renoitacaV
.seton fo stol ekat yehT
.tnuocca yrruFoS
,gninrael yad ruoy dneps uoy nehW tnedutS
.rehto hcae ot dna su ot ecin eb dna pu worg lliw yeht nehT
,salutaps dna snoops esu nac yeht snaem tahT
.tey wonk ton od ew ffuts erom neve si ereht tuB .tol a wonk sgoD tsitneicS   .ereht uoy ekat ot IA na ksa nac uoy ,tolip a ton era uoy dna erehwemos og ot deen uoy fI .stolip era snihplod fo stoL
.gniworg era stnalp eht woh leef ot ranos esu yeht esuaceb scinopordyh ta doog yrev era snihploD
.ybab a eb tsuj ot si boj ruoY .dliw llits yllacisab era uoy ,gnuoy yrev era uoy fI ybaB
.serutnevda ruoy tuoba raeh nac emoh ta sdneirf ruoy ,yaw tahT
.skcirt wen ecitcarp uoy pleh lliw yehT .snoitseuq gnirewsna dna gninialpxe ta strepxe era srehcaeT
.ti wonk dna noitamrofni daolnwod tsuj nac sIA rehcaeT
.elpoep ot sgniht gnirb sreiruoC .hguoht ,meht tnaw elpoep erehw ton era meht fo tsoM .sgniht doog fo stol sah esrevinU ehT reiruoC
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.sdnah evah yeht ecnis
,boj wen a yrt ot tnaw uoy fI
.ydaer era sloot ruoy dna naelc si esuoh ruoy erus ekam ot stobor esu yehT
.oot stneduts era stluda fo stoL
.ecin gnieb dna dlihc rieht gnihcaet sraey ynam sdneps tnerap A
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,god.ecioveht ta
snoitome rieht daer ot woh nrael yeht ,yaw tahT .seiceps rehto htiw ezilaicos ot nerdlihc rof tnatropmi si tI
.ti ta retteb hcum era sIA eht tub
.rettam dna thgil dna dnuos fo tuo tra ekam stsitrA .tra deen ew
.trid dna moor fo stol evah stenalp ecnis ,stenalp no era smraf tsoM
uoy dnuora god a ,sboj tuoba noitseuq a evah uoy fI
,skooc doog yrev era snamuH .skooc yb dekooc si doof suoiciled artxE .suoiciled artxe si taht doof tnaw uoy ,hguoht ,semitemoS
.sregrubeseehc gnitae dna ecaps ni gnirolpxe era dna
,boj ruoy ta doog ton era uoy ekil leef reve uoy fI
.krow fo tol a si tI
,retaw ylno dna trid on evah smraf esohT
.tneinevnoc yrev si tahT
.og ot erehw selcihev dna spihs llet stoliP toliP
.detacilpmoc eb nac sgnileeF tsiparehT
.tonnac sgod dna snihplod dna snamuH
.IA reltub a sah netfo gnidliub rehto ro esuoh A .sreltub reven erew snihploD
.tuo meht yrt dna sgniht esoht ekam yeht nehT .sgniht wen ekam ot woh tuo erugif sreenignE .sgniht wen gnitnevni ta doog sa ton tub ,sgniht gnirebmemer dna sgniht gnidliub ta doog yrev era sIA reenignE
tnerapollA ro tneraP
.enicidem dellac si tahT
,sreltub eb ot desu sgod dna snamuh emoS .sreltub era sIA tsoM
.spihs gib yllaer ro snoitats ecaps no era smraf emoS
.sgnileef ruoy leef dna dnatsrednu uoy pleh yehT
.gnihtyreve ta doog eb nac eno oN
.gnihtyna eb nac yeht tub
.llewyraeB yb cisum htiw
.gniklat dna pihsdneirf ekil
.peels ot deen ton od yeht esuaceb ,sreiruoc era sIA fo stoL
.efil ruoy ni semit tnereffid ta sboj tnereffid evah nac uoY
,semitemos su etib seibab hguoht nevE
,tah yobwoc a ni god yffulf
.uoy pleh nac rotcod a
dellac secalp ta stnalp esoht worg eW .stnalp fo stros lla esu snihplod dna snamuh dna sgoD remraF
.sboj fo stros lla tuoba deklat evah eW
.sgnileef fo stol evah snamuh dna snihplod dna sgoD tsitrA
si yrots s’yadoT dna
RUOF RETPAHC FO DNE
.syad tsom od uoy ytivitca laiceps a si boj A
era uoY .das eb ton od oS
seires dliW sexiS dna llafdniW eht fo retirw eht dna ,d'F yllarutluC ta retirw ffats eht si ohw
,hguoht ,semitemoS .sliat ruo gnivom ro gniklat yb sgnileef ruo erahs nac ew ,yllausU
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ti xif ot dna uoy htiw gnorw si tahw tuo erugif ot ygolonhcet gnisu ta strepxe era yehT
.yako si taht tub ,stsitra doog ton era sIA
.si ecin tahw nrael yeht os meht ot ecin eb ot evah ew
.stnalp eht fo erac ekat pleh ot stobor esu sremraF .smraf
,tfilpuP“ saw sihT
.seulc esoht tuoba gnikniht dna
.esoom taht gnitae neht dna—esoom a gnitnuh rof dezimitpo era sniarb dna seidob ruO
nuK'O epmeT yb
.noitamrofni nrael ot evah eW
.seinoloc dna spihs dna serutcurtsagem wen dliub sIA pleh dna
.slacimehc esoht uoy evig lliw yeht ,slacimehc thgir eht gnikam ton si ydob ruoy fI
.yrgnuh eb ot elpoep tnaw ton od ew ecnis ,doog si tahT .sdoof elpmis ekam ot senihcam evah eW .tnatropmi yrev si dooF kooC
noitats a ro tenalp a no krow thgim yehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
!yretsym eht devlos evah uoy ,no gniog si tahw tuo dnif uoy nehW