.tuo eugnot rie dekop eaDwA ”.ahsaS ,esaelP“
.elihw a rof ytisrevinu eht ta krow ot deunitnoc dah yE
.ten‘ eht no srehto ot larutan sa tsuj emac ,demees ti ,me ot larutan tlef taht yaw a ni gnicafretni fo tra eht ta gnivorpmi dna gnikroW
.riapsed-kcom fo kool a detpoda eaDwA
— srehto naht esnetni erom emos
.tsiaw rie dnuora deit ye hcihw
.meht taeper stneduts on os sraey evif yreve ecno syalp emas eht gniod
.kcats lanigiro eht morf tuo flesti delffuhs sdracv fo tes rehtona dna ,erutseg eht dehsinif ehS
.nwod delooc ti sa stsilkcehc detamotua hguorht gnikcit metsys elohw eht ,sredils eht
,yldiugnal dehctertS
.detaudarg ye retfa raey a naht ssel emac nodnoL morf llac ehT
.repaehc erehwemos
taht gnikniht er’eW .slatipsoh emos
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,oga sraey neetfif ekil tuo emac uoY“
”.peeb a draeh tsuj I
kcilc yrotagilbo eht dna ,deppaT
,kao ni delenap evocla na ot me thguorb yrenecs fo egnahc eht htiw gnola tnew taht
,ygrene rie fo lla pu nekat dah gir eht dna dnuos ,ereht morF
.ilumits fo smetsys elohw ot gnidnopser snoitca dna ,snoitcaer ,stcnitsnI
”,mM“  ”.detros meht teg uoy pleh lliw JR
”?ti t’nsi ,ereht etal s’tI“
— liat a htiw llew dekrow
.egats eht no rehtegot pmulc dna emutsoc-flah rieht fo tuo teg ot wols erew srotca ehT
.seye nwo rie htiw llah suonrevac eht gniees ot detsujda ye sa deknilB .tuo dekcab dna
”.lla si ,gnikniht em tog tsuJ
,teerts eht fo llihc eht otno tuo yaw rie edam JR ,yllautnevE  .sdnah owt
”?uoy t’now ,sretlif ruoy nesool ,xof ,no emoC“ “.ahcahS“
— eulc yna saw noitasrevnoc s’thginot fi ,nekorbnu deniamer taht gnirts a
,moor eht emaceb ye
.cincip utpmorpmi nA
,oreciC no yllanif dethgila sthguoht s’JR ,retal
.sdrac eht no sthgir ypoc tnarg ot erutseg a fo elddim eht ni thguac
.hcet evisremmi gnisu ylneddus erew dlrow eht dnuora sretaeht dna
— tes ytreporp tnecs on htiw seititne gnikwag owt ro enO
.uoy llet ot gniyrt saw I tahw s’taht ,haeY !hO“
,mrots a pu gnirrup detrats ehs litnu semit wef a liat ot srae morf ylhtooms reh dekorts
.hcaer reve dluow gnihctarcs on taht hcti na ot del — repeed raf ,raf
.dne s’dnuos no thgin txen eht litnu thgit peels dluow gnihtyrevE
.riaffa ylkeew a erew spirt bup epuorT
,os ylgnihsinaV .erar saw tsol gnitteg dnA
.me ta tuo depmuj yllaer ,revewoh ,enoN
uoy eht gnidliub rof egnahcxe yrtlap revlis fo lufdnah A
.enilno enipluv erom emoceb ot ecnahc a syawlA
,ton emos dna tsenrae emos ,spihsnoitaler rehto fo gnirts a evah ot no enog dah ahsaS
.dap wap a htiw tops eht gnibbur erofeb ,elbat eht ta walc a gnikop ,daeh rie koohs xof ehT ”?yllaeR ?tahW“
.snoitatupmoc sseltnuoc fo taeh etsaw eht eldnah ot
.denilcer dna dehcterts tI
.enif tsuj epuort eht fo ynapmoc eht deyojne yE
.denaorg dna swap rie ni ecaf rie deirub eaDwA nehw dehgual ahsaS
.kcab eht tsniaga gnitser dna ylisae ti otni gnidils
.deb ot revo gnilbmuts erofeb tuo erew sthgil eht dna dekcol saw rood eht erus gnikam no desucof ye ,owt deraen ti sa ,won roF .retaL
.peels ot ti dnes ot gir rie no nwod neercs eht deppilf yE
.kcab degnosgnis srotca eht fo eno ”,nossnahoJ retsiM ,seY“
— setirefretni eht ,sregnif rie no stcatnoc eht sa llew sa ,gir ehT
,hsid hserf a otni doof yrd fo puc a depoocs dna retnuoc eht no yawa-ekat rie tes yE
.dnuownU .dexaler tI
?scim eht fo lla rehtegot gnillup trats uoy naC
.gnihtemos ro srehcaelb eht htaeneb dessiK .seivom eht ot tuo tneW
.gnigrof dna gninoh
,rodirroc lartnec eht gnola nwot yna ni retaeht loohcs hgih gnihcaet eb dluoc uoY
.gnihcti eht neeb dah tsrow ehT
.regnil ti tel ,lleH
.sniffum fo reh dednimer syawla llems eht taht gninialpxe ahsaS
.lla retfa ,evisremmi ylurt saw hcet riE
.ti fo devorppa yllautca reven tub
.yratnemelpmoc dna dehctamsim nat no ruf kcalb
tsuj I ,hcus dna lasraeher tuoba klat uoy emit yreve ,wonk uoY“ .dennirg ahsaS
.flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daertprecxe na
.yttik tseitterp eht saw ehs ,tcaf ni
,gnigrof dna gninoH
.esnes tseurt eht ni deidobmesiD
.noitanimur eht egdolsid ot daeh rie koohs yE
.noitcennoc eht ecneirepxe ylluf erom me depleh taht enips rie nwod krow lufniap taht fo lla
,knuks eht etisoppo riahc eht ot revo gnivom dna thgiarts trihs rie gniggut ,deddon xof ehT
.tesdaeh a tog ,ssob yeH“
.snoitartsinim eltneg s’JR hguorht eno yb eno deb ot gniog ,ffo gningis erew srekaeps esohT
,thgim dik yna sa ,srehto ni ton dna sesruoc emos ni llew did yE
.srae ro seye ro ecaf on ,osrot on ,sbmil oN
”?ypoc a ekam I fi dniM“
.ti dellac yeht ,ygolonhcet retaeht evitcaretni evisremmI
.no gniog hcum ton dna ,yadkeew a no thgindiM
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,won thgir hcum oot od t’nac I
yE retaeht eht ni draob dnuos dlo s’loohcs eht gnikrow ni no ylrae detrats dah yE
.secnamrofrep evil ot retal dna ,seivom ot gniog fo dnert eht deunitnoc dah yehT
”.naem I ,rehtegot gnieb meht fO
.ti tuoba em lleT“
.saw ydaerla eno tahw ta
.drawrof me evord taht ygrene fo stsug eguH
,krow ta ydob a fo tpecnoc s’eno evlossid ot tub ,esruoc fo ,erew lla yehT
?trats ye dluoc nehW ?seY
,”nerdlihc ,dnuor‘ rehtaG“
”.yad yna yug daehkcid emos revo uoy ekil xof a ekat d’I .skcid era neM“
.daeh rie koohs dna dehgual eaDwA
”.tib a ni kcab eb ll’I“
,taht reh gnimrofni
,sbonk rotinom eht fo lla neht ,sevlesmeht gnitneiro sbonk niag eht fo lla
,gnigrof dna gninoH
.kcohs a neeb dah oreciC gnisoL .tsol eht no
.tner nodnoL retfa tfel saw tahw htiw yub ot sgniht retteb dah eaDwA dna ,yenom dneps ot syaw fo egatrohs on saw erehT
,rehtegot htaerb dleh-gnol ,wols a tuo tel moor eht dna JR
.kcab gnillup fo ssecorp eht detrats yltnatculer dna gniooc eltneg htiw moor eht dehtoos JR
.tnessa rieht derumrum niltiaC dna ,iaraS ,JR
,ydaeh oot saw retaeht eht fo ward eht tub ,seiduts rie gniunitnoc deredisnoc dah yE
me nioj ot allicsirP rof moor hguone gnivael ,sserttam eht dna srevoc eht otni repeed flesme gniyruB
rof tfel dah etamtalf tsal rie retfa me htiw ecaps rie erahs ot eno ylno eht saw ehS
.tac etaciled eht rof elit eht no ti gnittes
.dennirg nossnahoJ  ”?emoc woH“
.werc dna tsac eht fo tser eht ot selballys wef regaem a naht erom eraps t’ndluoc dna ,deb ot retaeht eht gnittup ysub saw yE
retteb emoceb ot yaw a syawlA
,meht evoba gnipiws dna kcats a otni kcab meht gnilffuhs erofeb flesme fo tnorf ni srie dennaf dna kcab kced s’ahsaS dils eaDwA .ecnelis ni tas owt ehT
”.boj a sa pu taht nekat dna pu nworg gnivah sa uoy erutcip ot em rof drah s’tI
,niks rie fo ecafrus eht dehcaerb xetrocoxe dna stnalpmi eht erehw ,enips rie gnola dna sdnah rie no elbaraeb saw tI
.noitanimur eroM
.sgnidnuorrus derrulb gnigrof susrev gninoh fo sthguohT
,srellortnoc CFN eht morf noitingocer fo egniwt elttil eht dna
,enirehtaC dna haraS nehT“ .derumrum JR
.paehc saw ti dna
”.xof ,uoy rof tuo gnikool tsuj ,yrros ,yeH“
.mom rie fo me dednimer taht yrruc eht htiw gnola og ot dad rie fo me dednimer taht ffuts eht fo emoS
,htuoy morf revotfel yromem a ,snoilednad fo ffihw tcnitsid eht ta deltsirb sreksihW
.gninoh fo eno krow
.nwal eht ni snoilednaD .ekilmaerd
.sserttam eht fo egde eht ot dils dna deb ni pu tas eaDwA  #  .ti
.me evoba yltcerid droc a morf suoludnep gnignah sthgil dedahs-ssalg-neerg yb til
.kced eht fo ypoc lacol a ekam ot gir rie gnitcurtsni
.dnE tsaE eht no stnemtrapa fo noitcelloc esool a dah epuort eht tub ,trats ot wols eb dluow yap ehT
.emit a ta spets owt nwod mrof yknal rie yrrac ytivarg gnitteL
.lla si ,taht rof ksa ot drah s’tI“
.hguoht ,elbaliava eb tseB
.tac eht demrofni ye ”,acsirP ,depiw m’I“
.lasraeher fo ssenesnet eht morf gnidniwnu ,revoc tip eht fo egde eht no tas yehT
.no ylrae gnitad deirt dah ahsaS dna yE
.emit no ereht eb d’yeht wenk JR tub ,gnilbmurg erom tib a saw erehT
”.oreciC dekil lla eW .rehtie ,ot ton nosaer oN
.me tuohtiw no devom dah dlrow eht syaw ynam oS
.hcton a pu detehctar sselehtenon srruP
.ten‘ eht no sdneirf rie gnoma yal traeh rie tuB
.tohsrettacs dna mid ,mlif tuo nrow A
.oot ti ssim I ,gnorw em teg t’noD .loohcs ni od ot devol uoy tahw gniod llits er’uoY
.gnigrof dna gninoh
,thgir ot tfel wap a derutseg dna dap eht no thgiarts doots yE .ycar
.tsewhtroN cificaP eht ni rohtua na si ohw
.yrd dna naelc sregnif rie fo stnioj elddim eht no stcatnoc eht peek ot sevolg foorpretaw niht rie no gnillup
.flesti egats eht fo kcalb ettam eht no sleeh fo palc ehT .elffucs A
.dne eht drawot hsigguls elttil a tog syug uoy ,werC
ffo me tup os ssecorp eht htiw gnola tnew taht xes fo noitatcepxe eht tub ,spahrep ,noitcartta citnamor fo egniwt lanoisacco eht tlef d’yE
.reduol derrup ehS
,tuo dekrow t’ndah gnitad erehW
.oot ,kool a ekat ll’I“
.parc taht lla ,deirram nettog
pu daeh reh detnub ehs nehw srae reh revo gnikorts ,tac gnirrup-llits eht drawot revo degdurt dna taes rie fo tuo pu flesme derevel yE
.yltsom ,sdneirF .samora fo dworc lausu eht dna — stsiruot
.sdneirf rie fo yna naht me rof erom spahreP
.sdnekeew eht no uoy htiw swohs yzarc gnieeS .ffuts loohcs eht ton ,retaeht lautcA
.ot ton denoituac neeb dah ye hguoht ,hctarcs dluoc ye tsael ta esuaceb
.worromot lla uoy hctac ll’I dna ,thginot tser emos teG
— fles dna xof fo maglama thguorw ylenif a ,on
.llaw eht no sregrahc derebmun otni detekcos sdnah eht fo lla morf stesdaeH
,hcet noitargetni eht no deiler ye hcum woh tsuj fo rednimer prahs a saw tI .drah tih tahT
,me ot esolc os ward eht htiw nevE
,stnalpmi no krow taht ereht dnuora sretnec wef a dna ,ylimaf eht rof ofni tcatnoc s’erehT“
.moor eht ssorca morf allicsirP deltrats noitom dna dnuos ehT
— enilno ecalp koot tahw ytilaer ni tuo gnitca morf me peek ot scitylaraportcele eht dna ,sevren yrotidua dna citpo rie revo koot taht stnalpmi elacsonan
:”desirprus“ ,llew ,rO
,esrepsid ot detrats dna dehgual epuort ehT
,tnaem gnicafretni erom dna ,gnicafretni erom tnaem ten‘ eht no gnieb sdneirf riE
.xes evah t’ndid yeht dedneterP
.evisremmi tnew gir ehT
.enoyreve ,thgirlA“  .ylwols
.gnihcnurc dna gnirrup yb decalper swoem tnangidnI
”.ruof ta ereh kcab ,thgin worromoT“
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”htelehoQ“ saw sihT
.spitregnif rie ssorca dils taht sliated eht fo wef a ni gnikat dna ylwols hguorht gnifael
”?pu derehtag scim eht lla teg uoy diD
.ti nori dluohs ye ebyaM
s’errabeD .raed ,ti tuoba yrrow t’noD“ .dehgual ahsaS
gnikcilc seitilaer motnahp esoht llA
.efil laicos rie fo erahs s’noil eht rof tub ,krow rof ylno ton
.hcterts a fo hcum oot t’nsaw tI
.struh reven hsilop erom tib a ,llitS
,stnecs railimaf emoS
.xelf ot selcsum srekaeps ehT .sevren seriw ehT
.evocla na naht rehtar tnemtrapa oiduts eht fo renroc a ni srie tpek ye
,ysword ,loohcs fo seiromeM
.ti htiw emoc dah taht asomas yggos eht dna yrruc egnaro gnirab
.meht tuoba dias eciC tahw nevig ,sseug I ,gnisirprus taht lla toN
”.ot tnaw I wonk uoY“
,boj dooG“  .rethgual deriT
,delward ye ”,emaL“
.retaeht yzod eht htiw seton rie hguorht gniog tuoba tes ye elihw gnitcartsid erew revoc tip eht no daeh sih depmub ssoR sa esruc lanoisacco eht dna gnihtaerb fo sdnuos tfos ehT
.evoba morf ffo gningis ,peY“
.ytic eht otni repeed gnivom saw ohw dneirf a morf deucser dah ye taht sraey wef a fo gniht regnig elttil A
.epahs esrevid fo seidob dnuora gnitriks
,thgin eht fo llihc eht tsniaga srevoc eht htaeneb deworrub dna sserttam worran rie otno debmilc ye sa nevE
.enecs elohw eht drawot yhtapa etelpmoc s’JR yb ylno delauqe saw loohcs hgih tuohguorht etad ot erusserp laicos eht fo ytisnetni ehT
,saw-ti-sa-nodnoL ni kcab ,JR rof saw ti sa krad sa tsuj saw ,selsi hsitirB eht fo mhtyhr naidacric eht gniwollof ylegral ,mis bup ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
nib tsopmoc eht otni reniatnoc eht gnissot sa ysae sa pu naelC
,tip eht ni dekcats era sexob ehT
.elihw a rof slasraeher ni neeb ev’uoy wonk I dna ,ereht etal s’tI .thgirla s’ti ,oN“
.strecnoc nar yE .syalp nar
,prahs oot elttil a erew taht sepirts etihw yb dekram kcalb yklis ,neve na saw ruf s’ahsaS erehW
”.noitamrofni notsal sih gniliated drac a osla
”?hguoht ,deneppah tahw s’taht demrifnoc tsael ta yehT
tsacdop a sa yllaires desaeler gnieb si hcihw
,tserdaeh eht tsniaga daeh rie gnitliT .eldarc sti otni dnah tfel rie tes yE
.ytisrevinu erofeb erudecorp eht me desimorp dah yeht dna ,nosrep gnikniht-drawrof ylriaf a rehtom rie dna reenigne na saw rehtaf rie
.noitapicitna eht hsileR .thguoht ye
.noitpecrep rie fo segde eht dnuora desaet seitilaer motnahP
.lliks taht gninoh llitS .dnuos gninnur llitS
.nigol dna toob gnirud elor sti devres llits ,edisni saw ye nehw laigitsev tub lla ,neercs ehT
.werc eht fo tser eht htiw meht denioj
.eno gnitnaw yllautca
.dap tropt eht fo ecafrus yssolg eht tsniaga dekcalc swalc ,ereht morF
.guh kciuq a rof ni nael dna pu dnats ot kcab riahc reh gnitoocs ,dehgual ahsaS
.yaw eht gnola spohs yhtrowtsurt erom eht fo eno morf ecir dna yrruc fo notrac yawa-ekat a pu kcip ot deppotS
,htelehoQ levon reh morf senecs wef tsrif eht sesirpmoc sihT
.daeh sih ffo tesdaeh eht deggut eh sa dessarrabme dekool neht ,depmuj ssoR
”.peels emos teg oG
.krow hcet retaeht ni egnahc eht leuf depleh ytisrevinu eht ta seiduts nwo rie taht wen os neeb dah dleif ehT
.gnihtyreve gnidleif er’yehT
.tupni yrosnes wen a sllaw eht gnireppep sciM
.talf rie ot ereht morf skcolb wef eht klaw
,ees dluoc sklof erehw ecnetsixe fo tuo dna ni pop ot saw ti sa ehcuaG
.evil tnew yeht erofeb tsal eht saw lasraeher s’thgin txen ehT
,nac I nehw kool a gnikat m’I ,ti no gnikrow
”.retaeht a evah llits ew erus ekam ot ereh kcab lla uoy tnaw I dna neht dnuora pu sdniw taht noitcudorp loohcs a s’erehT“
.edistuo nodnoL fo llihc pmad eht retfa talf elttil rie fo htmraw eht democlew dna tekcaj rie fo tuo deppils ye ,emoh ecnO
.haey tuB“ .tsal t’ndid tI .dennirg ahsaS
,gnigrof dna gninoH
”,tsrif ,sdael eht barG“
.wor tnorf eht ni nwod morf gniyas saw nossnahoJ
”?yako ,sgniht fo pot no peek tub ,drah oot sevlesruoy krow t’noD
.noihsaf citcamilc emos ni gnidne naht rehtar ,tuo deretep pihsnoitaler ehT
gnihtemos gnittel ,hceeps rie no sretlif tuptuo eht kcab delaid tub
,tnecserc llams a otni delruc dna pal rie otni delttes taC
“–t’ndluow ti wonk uoy ,ahsaS“
.nworf ylno dluoc eaDwA hcihw ot ,daeh reh koohs ehS
buP nworC ehT :tropt
.gnihtemos enO .etal oot toN“
,krow fo yrruls a ni derednuof dnim riE
”.uoy ekil ereht tuo syug erom erew ereht hsiw tsuj I .wonk I ,oN“
.gir a htiw gnicafretni lluf rof dedeen stnalpmi eht htiw me desirprus dah stnerap rie ,yadhtrib htneetxis rie rof dna ,llew sa me detavitpac dah sessalc retupmoc suoirav ehT .egitserP
.no tnew ti neht dnA .eerhT
,moor eht fo renroc eht ni resserd eht ot deddap dna doots cennef eht ,nwod ruf rie gnihsurB .ecalp otni
.srehto eht fo lla htiw gnola
.liat motnahP .srae motnahP .ruf motnahP
dna allicsirP pu dekcip yE .emit rie koot ye
.yal dluow daeherof rie erehw tserdaeh deddap ,tfos eht decalper yltnecer dah yE
.dias JR ”,ylraE“
?thgir ,slrig dna syob doog rehto htiw evol ni llef slrig dna syob dooG
.srotca eht rof puekam dna enoyreve rof sserd lluf naem dluow lasraeher s’worromoT
,boj s’niltiaC dna JR elihw ,yalp eht ni no gniog saw tahw fo egdelwonk rieht ot gnidnopser
.dracv a htiw delddif
.gniparcs sriahC .stohs-nuG
”?knuks ,neeb uoy woH“ .ssap hsilgnE gnilbmeser ylesolc erom
”.etal nar lasraeheR .tsael ta emoh emit doog edaM
.hguoht ,esolc os enoemos esol oT
naht rehtar pihsnoitaler a gnivah otni derusserp tlef dah yeht taht dettimda htob dah yeht ,erehwyna gniog ton ti fo skeew wef a retfA
,erus eb ot ,seitilamrof llA
tniop renif dna renif a ot flesme denoh dah eaDwA
.hcet wen a fo tnorferof eht ta eb dluow ye taht tnaem osla ti tub
.eb ot tuo denrut s’ti lla toN“
.niats wolley a gnivael ,dnah rie fo kcab eht no srewolf eht fo eno gnibbuR
.yllacitegolopa dennirg eaDwA ”.enif er’uoy ,on ,yrroS“
s’erehT .pu dnuow eh erehw secalp fo sepyt eht eb thgim esoht
,lla fo tsal deb ot stesdaeh eht fo lla tup dna ssoR htiw lennahc eht desolc yE
.ti fo tuo tog ye erom eht ,ksat eht otni tup ye erom eht taht denrael ylkciuq ye neht yb tub ,esruoc fo ,nuf neeb syawla t’ndah tI
saw tahw ,noitatressid riE
.potelbat tned walc gnittel no selcyc etsaw ot hguone evisremmi yldrah saw mis ehT
.thgil mid ylevitarapmoc eht ot tsujda ot deknilb yE
,secnerefnoc dna serutcel dna seilbmessa nar yE
,liated gnitcaxe ot xof cennef a sa flesme fo noisrev a tcurtsnoc ot derobal dah eaDwA
.gurhs dezistuo na gnivig ,elbat eht no sdracv fo kcats a htiw delddif dna riahc reh otni kcab delttes ahsaS
,enod esohT .lohocla gnibbur dna repap eerf-tnil htiw sdnah rie no stcatnoc eht gninaelc tuoba tes ye
,me fo tnorf ni dnuora sdrac fo kcats eht detsiwt eaDwA
”,pu gnikcap trats ot emit ,thgindim s’tI
— xof a fo taht otni tpecnoc emas yrev eht praw ot emoh emoc neht dna
”.drah hsarc ot gnitrats m’I tub ,ereh tog tsuj I wonk I .gniog teg attog I ,ahsaS ,yeH“
.ssoR ot nepo peek ot deen d’ye lennahc eht sunim llA
.meht otni thguoht emos tup dah srenwo eht taht eaDwA dlot hcihw
,dekrow JR sa lartuen ot gninruter fo ksat eht tuoba tes draob pu-kcab lacisyhp ehT
.ecneirepxe yrosnes wen a saw tI
.me rof gnitiaw tros tnereffid a fo bup a eb dluow erehT
.srehto htiw gnitcaretni nehw desu ye taht anosrep yramirp eht gnitfarc ylwols
:htob werc dna tsaC
”.hguoht ,gniyrt uoy etaicerppa I
.nehctik eht ot me dewollof ,tnangidni ,woem A
.retaeht eht nevE .siht ni stsohg eb ot dah yehT
.htob krow evil dna smliF
,deliated tsael ta meht fo tsom tub ,railimafnu emos
.swap naidisbo no gnitser elzzum ,swoble reh otno drawrof denael dna seye reh dellor knuks ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,gnigrof dna gninoH
.gurhs ot nrut s’eaDwA ”.retteb
.gnigrof dna gninoh fo ,ahsaS htiw loohcs fo ,ecnaraeppasid s’oreciC fo
.tniop enif a ot denoh anosrep A
.tuo gnihsurb-elttob rettal eht ,liat ot rae morf eltsirb ruf tel
.tsom eht dias detatsrednu eht ,ssecxe fo semit eseht ni
.swohs ruo era os tub ,etal s’ti wonk I
.deddon dna ylsuoituac delims ahsaS
.saw ye tlef eaDwA eaDwA eht erom emoceb oT
.daeh rie fo tuo ,won edaced tsal siht enog ,loohcs hgih fo klat reh fo lla dna ahsaS gnikahs on eb ot demees erehT
.ruf motnahp tsap gnihsurb sezeerb motnahp leef dluoc yE
”?haey ,knuks ,retal uoy ees ll’I“
.ksir erom ,demees ti
.inu ni swohs yzarc gniod ,lleH
,erom gniklat ,erom tuo gnignah detrats yehT
,me erofeb tuo daerps notrac eht htiw elbat nehctik eht ta enola eta JR
.ereh m’I ,ssoR yeH“
.yaw eht fo tuo dna talf gniyal srae enipluv
”?trats ot em tnaw uoy od erehW
.loohcs morf seiromem gniyalper saw ye
”?niaga tuo kcurts ,on hO“
.gnihctiwt eson ,reporp bup eht otni dedaeh dna deggurhs xof ehT
.moor eht gnimoceb saw tI
,gnigrof dna gninoH
.esuoh eht fo weiv reh
.ereht deppots dah JR tub
,eciffo tneitaptuo na ni erudecorp drawrofthgiarts a saw tI
.ti ni pu thguac teG
”.won gnipeels si esuoh ehT
.tneserp tub ,teiuQ
,doots dna ti raelc ot daeh rie koohs yE
— kcen rie fo kcab eht no ytilaer fo ezeerb looc taht rof tleF
,yalp eht fo egdelwonk cidepolcycne s’reganam egats eht ot dnopser ot saw
”…gir toh a revo gnivals ,drah oot gnikrow oN
,ylevitcepser sthgil dna dnuos sa
.ydob eht fo noitulossid a saw tI
pu dekcip naf gnilooc a fo muh tfos eht
2112 - retswerB JR  )flesreh rohtua eht yb daer ,tprecxe na(
?wonk uoy ,htoob dnuos eht revo dehcnuh uoY
,tsael ruf eht htiw derefretni osla tI
.loohcs fo tol a em dnimer tsuj uoy ,hguoht ylsuoireS“
.raed ,sbrub‘ eht ni ereh emit gib tuo gnissim er’uoY
— desremmi os kcen a rof dessap revetahw ro
,tcaxe oot elttil a
,gir rie ta nwod tis ot flesme dewolla yllanif yE
.tsael ta ,hcuot tsol reven dah yehT
”,acsirP ,ni daeh annoG“
.ti eriuqca ot sgnivas rie deniard dah yE
.flesym rof pu dnatS .ebyam ,niks rekciht a teg dluohs I“
,wonk uoy ,ecafrus eht no pihsnoitaler eht detroppus fo tros syawla yehT
.delttes raeg dnuos eht fo tsal eht teg ot ssoR dna JR rof setunim wef a koot ylno tI  ”.txen od ot tahw erus t’nsaw I
weiv otni ettelap dnammoc rie gnipiws ydaerla
.dnah rie tsniaga
snoitacilbup/kni.oykam ta elbaliava era hcihw tuo skoob lareves sah ehS
”.oot ,niaga uoy ees ot doog eb d’tI .emitemos su ees emoc dluohs uoY“
raeh regnol on dluoc yE
.loohcs ot kcab kniht
,ni devled JR sA
.sgab rie dekcap dna ,raey yreve tisiv dna emoc d’ye taht sesimorp rie edam yE .raf os tub
.retteb gniod eb llits dluohs I .eaDwA
,detubirtsid dna dehsilbup saw ,tcejorp enotspac elpmis a eb ot tnaem
hguoht ,daol eno ni tuo meht teg ot elba eb dluohs uoy ,llaw tnorf eht yb
.eno trohs er’ew ,ssoR“
— teliot eht gnisu ,srevotfel gnirots ,gninaelc ,gnitae
.dneirf rie fo tnecs noilednad taht ni gnilever eaDwA
”.hguoht ,sllib eht yap t’nseoD
.ecafretni eht morf kcab deppils ye erofeb
.ylimaf s’eciC htiw hcuot ni gnitteg retfa thgin eno gnirelloh errabeD
.tnew ye rehtruf eht ,denoh ye erom ehT
.tsol saw eh ,tsol ,tsoL
.enog d’uoy erehw gnirednow saw ,yrroS“
”?thgirla gniod eh sI
.JR no seitivarg eltbus gnitrexe saw moordeb rie fo renroc eht ni gir ehT
.srehcaet eht naht sretupmoc tuoba erom wenk ohw dik dnuos ydren eht ylpmis saw yE
,pu nworg dna tser eht lla ekil enod t’nevah uoY
.nwo reh ni ezeeuqs a swap s’xof eht evag ehS
.sesub thgin ,sbac kcalB
.tuo llihc nac uoy ,eraepsekahS ton s’tI
,reganam egats eht ,iaraS dna niltiaC
.yhtapitna ,netfo ,ro yhtapA
,emit a ta regnif eno ffo sevolg ruoy leeP
.elzzum enipluv ylhguoroht a fo seicacirtni eht fo enrob noitpurroc A
.tcatnoc no tnedive erew secnereffid tub ,swap ekil-dnah yltsom rof detpo dah htoB
.rohcna no
:srae lla ebyam rO
,secaps eciohc rehto wef a dna buP nworC eht hguorht ylsseltroffe devom yE
”.nezorf fo gnikaeps ,hO“
.enilffo eman rie pu edam taht srettel owt eht mrof neve t’ndluoc elzzum rie erehw tniop eht ot nwod
.rellams dna rellams werg stibro rie
.gnignahc saw epacstnecs eht ,saciremA eht ni neve gnineve eht ni no teg ot gnitrats saw ti taht woN
”.won tip eht ot nwod gnidaeh ,ti toG“
”.doof uoy teg I erofeb nwod tihs ym tup em tel ,acsirP yeH“
.gnicnivnoc dedeen dah stnerap riE
.krow retfa sdneirf rieht htiw pu hctac ot sbup eht gnitisiv elpoeP
.gnihcti erew sevolg riE
rebiforcim looc fo hcuot gnitrofmoc eht gnileef
.ezeeuqs eht denruter ,yltniaf delims eaDwA
,srae reh revo gnikorts ,tac rie ot derumrum ye
.yawa daeh reh koohs
,slirdnet gniyfimar rieht dna enilriah rie rednu tsuj detnalpmi snoitcennoc CFN eht
.srecafretni yvaeh erew lla ,tsol eht gnoma detnuoc erew ohw esoht gnoma ,llitS
.ecneidua denekrad eht ni tuo morf demoob eciov a
”.ruomalg fo efil a ylurT
,t’ndid ro deohce dnuos yaw eht gnileef
.gninoh otni gnigroF
,niltiaC dna iaraS htiw derahs ye krow ta htoob hcet eht ni ffuts eht naht etarobale erom saw emoh ta raeg riE
”.srehto ni gnideeccus er’uoy hguoht ,neve syaw wef a ni — kcuts fo dnik
.egami-fles rie ylesicerp erom tif ti ekam ot ,mrof eht tcefrep ot retteB
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.dlrow laer eht ot sevlesmeht detneiroer yeht sa regnol elihw elttil a rof revoc tip eht no gniregnil sdael hcet eht
tac eht litnu sdlof neetevlev ,tfos eht gniregnif
.drazah lanoitapucco ti llaC
.hcet retteb a eb ot yaw a syawlA
.gniyalp cisum trats ot enohp rie debmuht yE
.emit eht ta sesac derdnuh a spahrep htiw
.sevlesmeht gnillatsni ylegral stnalpmi dediug-fles
”,era eseht tahw s’tahT“
.ffats eht sa llew sa ,werc hcet rehto eht fo tsurt eht gninrae ylkciuq
.lautir a ni pets lanif ehT
,xaler seriw dna selcsum gnileef
.gnorw og syawla dluoc gnihtemoS
.ecnamor ot noisreva htiw gnola tnew taht amgits laicos yna tuoba yrrow ot emit elttil gnivael
,gnigrof fo efil a delleps aimedacA .gnirulla oot
.dehsurc dekool errabeD
.ecaf rie tsniaga ezeerB
.deretnuoc ye ”,taht uoy esimorp nac I ,nwo ym no yppah ytnelp m’I“
.lausu naht gniticxe ssel ro erom on saw renniD
.flesti ot demmuh tI .derrup retaeht ehT
.tpels yE .drawer dna ksiR
‘wabeD ,a-eehS‘ ekil erom tuo emac ti hguoht ,dias eaDwA ”,errabeD
.egats eht sdrawot sriats eht nwod htoob hcet eht morf gnilbma erofeb ,gnihcterts
.sdnammoc desu yltnecer fo tsil a pu gnignirb
uoy eht naht rehtar eb ot tnaem era uoy
.ksir ta os tlef ye yhw saw taht spahreP
.wol-nwod eht no tpek sekoj etavirP
”htelehoQ“   yojne esaelP  .fles-tsop/mf.rohcna
,me ot pu dettort tac riE
dna nwod kcab ruf rie elttes ot flesme koohs yE
.seye eht dnuora ytinamuh eht ,sdnah eht
.ti gnitneverp setirefretni eht morf pu tnep ,nway degdelf-lluf a tuo gnittel ,tserdaeh eht morf kcab denael dna seldarc eht morf sdnah rie dils JR  # .emoh daeh ot
,noitaredeF nretseW eht ni llitS
.kcapkcab dedaolrevo na ekil spu-kaerb dab fo aedi yrev eht pord ot elba eb thgim ehs hguoht sa ,niaga deggurhs ahsaS ”.ahsaS ,yrros m’I“
— repeed deddebme setirefretni eht dna daeherof rie ni sgat CFN ehT
.krow ni flesme deirub daetsni dah ye taht
,guh rehtona degnahcxe dna pu doots htoB
,daeh rie revo parts eht deluah dna gab redluohs a otni pihc tiderc detimil a dna sdracv wef a dekcut ye os
.derreferp eaDwA taht repap-nottoc ymaerc eht no dessobme kcalb psirC
.hsiwsa liat ,ezeeuqs a evag dna nrut ni tsiaw s’knuks eht dnuora smra rie deppils eaDwA
,ten‘ eht no ereht tuo snoihsaf tsehgih eht fo emos gninimaxe sruoh sseltnuoC
”.kcab meht gnikat luferac eb
.riahc eht fo sevruc railimaf eht otni gnixaler
.oga syad owt nees tsaL
,taht noisulcnoc eht ot emoc d’ye dna
.htdaerb dna htped htob ni werg pihsdneirf
.su sediseb tuo mih gnipleh srehto tog s’lesaew eht erus m’I dna
”.uoy ees ot doog s’ti os ,syad wef tsal eht revo ereh ni gnirob fo dnik neeB“
.enilno sreliater enif ynam morf ro
.tesdaeh eht otni snoitseuq detatiga gnirettum ,roolf eht ta gnirats dna llits gnidnats ,wor tnorf eht ni saw ssoR
,ylwols ,sevlesmeht elgnatnesid tnerruc dna sevren
.kcab gnillup fo gnileef nrobwen eht ot dedda ylno ria denoitidnoc dna tsud fo eton elbert ehT
.ezag reh derewol ahsaS ”.taht teg I ,oN“
.ti ekam dluow sboj dnoces htiw esohT
,neerG lahtneB ot pu enil lartneC .sucriC drofxO ot pu daetsni degdurt yE
.pu kcuf ot detnaw eno oN
niltiaC dna flesme dna ,reganam eht ,sdnah eht neewteb noitacinummoc gniganam emit hcum sa tneps ye
?ti nori ye dluohS
.gnigrof dna gninoh
,nwo rie ni swap reh fo eno ekat ot tuo dehcaer eaDwA .tcatnoc eye oN
.srosicni prahs fo yhs tsuj gnilruc eugnot knip rednels ,ylediw denway
.naelc saw xut rie erus ekam ot evah d’yE
,ssen-deggel-owt eht spahrep sunim ,gnitcaxE
”.netobrev gnerts tsi saD ,thgin worromot tub ,thginot knird nac uoy ,rebmemeR
.ereht er’ew kniht I
.selkna rie dnuora gniniwt
.erus eb ot tsuj no sevolg rie tfel yE
.rethgiarts pu tas ye ,hguoht ,tnemom a retfA
.sremrofrep eht morf dnuos eht gniniatniam did ye sa
,gnoras yvan elpmis a dna tnorf eht pu secal htiw trihs nottoc etihw niht a tuo gnillup
”.srekaeps eht hguorht klat ot evah t’nod I os ,ssoR ,tesdaeh a teG“
.metsys dnuos eht hguorht dereffo JR
?nwot ni puorg retaeht yvvas-hcet a trats pleh ot ekil ye dluoW
.pu dekcuf yeht fi elbisiv emoceb ylno dluow ti esuaceb ,ecneidua eht ot elbisivni eb dluohs taht seno erew sboj riehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitcidsiruj s’JR rednu saw dnuos llA
.gninnur flesme peek ot seirolac erom evah d’ye os noonretfa eht ni tuo gnidaeh erofeb ecir fo top lanoitidda na kooc d’ye taht flesme gnisimorp ,hcnul s’yad txen eht rof reniatnoc citsalp a otni yrruc eht fo tsal eht depoocs ,dehsinif yE
.tnemtraped dnuos eht fo nur lluf evah dluow yE
:yrtne eht revo egdums raelc a eb d’ereht ,enilno stnirpregnif tfel ye daH
,evocla eht drawot dworc eht hguorht kcab yaw rie gnikam erofeb ezeeuqs tsal eno knuks eht evaG
.snaej rie fo tuo deppils dna daeh rie revo ffo trihs rie deleep ye ,gnilimS
,srae owt ,seye owt yb detimil ,stniartsnoc laitaps yb dnuob dlrow A
”htelehoQ“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ylkciuq dedda dna srae reh deyalps ahsaS ,wodniw eht sdrawot yawa dekool dna taes rie ni deneffits eaDwA nehW
,tuo thgin elpmis a eb d’tI
”.rehtie ti tfel uoy ekil ton ,sediseB
,me ta deggut emoh gnidaeh erofeb tnip kciuq eno dna bup mraw a fo aedi ehT
.llew ti gniod dna boj sti gniod ni edirp fo esnes a leef ot demees retaeht eht nevE
.semitemos ,tsol gnieb ot esolc ylsuolirep tlef
.noitcudorp ni desu gnihtemoS
.pu nesool attog uoy ,haraS tub ,dexaler yltsom dna ,senil debbulf oN
”…gnitad pu gnirb uoy fI“
.kcalb ni lla pu enod lesaew eht morf tnurg truc a tog yE
.saciremA eht morf senecS
.bmuht rie htaeneb nottub eht degdun ye
.gnipoord liat ,deddon knuks ehT
.eman nesohc rie fo noitpurroc a ,eaDwA .cennef A
.hcnurc naht rehto semit rof saw ecir naht erom hcum gnikooC
.reeb fo taht naht regnorts hcum saw emoh fo llup eht tub
.elzzum worran s’xof eht morf gnimoc
?yako ,flesruoy fo erac ekaT“
,ylimaf rie htiw gnola dniheb sdneirf esolc rehto wef a dna ahsaS gnivael tnaem tI
”?I t’nod ,ti ni toof ym gnittup peek I .raed yrroS“
,gnitallitit saw yrenecs fo egnahc gnirraj eht dna erusopxe fo gnileef ehT
.gir rie no dil eht nepo pop ot hguone etelpmoc tlef yllanif JR ,denaelc raeg dna snoitcennoC  .ti htrow llA
.scim ecin eht tog ev’yeht
.si sa hguone naelC
,detanigiro tnecs eht erehw ,selbat wodniw eht fo eno sdrawot enileeb a edam ye dna
.tsaoc tsae eht no tuo ytisrevinu eman gib a ta pihsralohcs a ni detanimluc dah tnemnorivne retaeht lautriv eht fo gnigrof ehT
.levart saw sa tsuj ,demussa dah enoyreve ,ksir a saw tI
.mM“ ”.sLCA uoy evig ll’I tub ,etelpmoc toN .no gnikrow neeb evah I dna errabeD kced a s’tI .daeha oG“
?erutan esab s’eno yned yhW
— gnineve laticer-tsop eht fo snoitom eht hguorht nar ye sA
.pu ti kcab ot erawdrah eht dna retaeht a htob htiw dnuora secalp wef eht fo eno saw tI
,ay eeS“ .evocla eht sdrawot gnilbmuts lesaew rednels a gnidiova ylworran
.tfihs-txetnoc eht hsinif ot scinomenm sseldrow spahrep ro
.stceffe dnuos eht fo yna pu kcip ot ton erac ekat ot evah d’yeht nehw sediseb seuc wef a sulp ,senil s’enoyreve nrael ot dah owt ehT
.noitacitnehtua fo srotcaf owt rie fo flah rehto eht stcatnoc rie morf noitcennoc ehT
.etanutrofnu s’tahT“
,oreciC fo erac gnikat s’taht revetahw ro cinilc eht htiw hcuot ni teg ot gniyrt neeb s’eH .tey ,swen oN“
.lla secnatniauqcA
.erom ecno moor eht ni stnecs eht nacs ot ecnelis eht morf yawa tuons rie detfil yE
— eerf pils taht tel gnoras eht fo htgnel eht nwod tuc tils elpmis a
,tnemom a rof detatiseh ahsaS
”,pu gnimoc wohs a tog ev’uoy ,wonk I“ “–a tog ev’I
.troffe rie fo lla depmud ye ,deyojne ye stcejbus eht ni tub
!yawa raf os ,nodnoL tub ,erus eb ot ,desaelp erew yehT
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.tsrif ta ,ecnaraeppasid A
.erehwemos yawa dehsats ytinamuh fo eerf va na dah ye ,neht nevE
,werc gnithgil eht dna JR htiw krow ylpmis ot saw boj s’retaeht ehT
.me dnuora duolc a ni gnignah noitanimur ,deddon eaDwA
.rehtegot sdneirf fo krowten a gnidliub
.dworc eht gninnacs ylpmis naht tneserp esoht fo erom me dlot moor eht fo stnecs ehT
,nezorf fo dnik mees uoY
.yaw lacisyhp ylpeed a ni srekaeps eht fo stimil eht gniwonk
.sthgin krow no esle gnihtyna did ylerar ye
”.pu nworg t’nevah uoy syaw eht fo lla fo esuac‘ s’ti ebyaM
.gnihtyreve dna ti rof inu ot tnew I ?ti t’nsI“
.gnigrof dna gninoh
,dap eht morf yawa deppets dna denrut yE
.ecalp ni dnah rie dleh taht sevoorg railimaf gnidnif sregnif ,dap devruc eht no dnah thgir rie detser neht dna esarhpssap rie ni deyek ylkciuq yE
.me ot revo sdracv fo kcats eht gnippils ,dias ahsaS
”.dlo emas ,dlo emas ,wonk uoy ,hO“
.lasraeher gnol a retfa ot deen ydaerla d’ye naht erom stcatnoc rie naelc ot gnivah ni esnes oN
.yaw eht ni gnitteg neeb s’ylimaf eht tub
.yna flesym tressa ot mees t’nac ,neht neve dna ,ereh ni gnidih thgin retfa thgin dneps I
.esac ni tsuj nepo lennahc eht tfel JR
.pihsredael deniag ye neht dnA
.retaeht eht dna mE .tsac eht fo tsom naht retteb wohs eht wenk yE
.neht ,esab ot kcaB“
,dab t’nia nodnoL ,yeh tuB
.yna nialpmoc t’nac I
.emitgnirps MA nevele lauteprep a ni devil mis lanosrep rie tub
.daeha degrof esle enoyreve elihw
.xob rieht htiw pu sehctam taht edis emutsoc eht no detniap rebmun ynit a evah dluohs meht fo llA
.tserdaeh eht morf kcab denael dna stniop tcatnoc eht morf deppils sregnif rie detfiL
.neppah syawla dluoc gnihtemoS
.deddon xof ehT ”?errabeD“
,erom ecno deggurhs ,deddon ,deggurhs ahsaS
.sgnignoleb lanosrep fo lanesra gniwolg ylmid a gnilaever ,resserd eht pota thgir ot tfel morf wap rie depiws yE .era uoy
.ytinummoc eht ot me decudortni taht reh saw ti rof ,gnitcennoc detrats yllaer dah ahsaS dna ye taht neht saw tI
.evah uoy syaw eht lla etipsed ,degnahc t’nevah uoy taht ,reilrae tnaem I tahw s’taht kniht I“ ”.neeb sah syawlA
.ssenisword otni gnigde noitanimuR
.ereht detcelloc dah taht slio niks dna taews fo eudiser elbigilgen eht gnivomer ,tesdaeh eht nwod depiw ye
.noissergorp larutan a tsomla demees loohcs hgih ni yrruf dnuof dah ye tahT