.yhw ees dluoc eh dna ,ereht rednu kool t'ndid mom sih nevE
.lamron yltcefrep erew gnihtyreve fi sa tca dna
.yllautca ,dab toN
.elbat eht no sgnivael hciwdnas eht gnoma morf wolg tniaf a saw erehT
"?uoy pleh I yam woH"
,elkcuhc a htiw thguoht eh
.dnuos eht etacol ot yrt ot htrof dna kcab daeh sih gninrut
,deb ni ton flesmih dnuof eH
,teef sih ta nwod dekool eH
.yllanoisacco detisiv eh pohs hciwdnas thgin-lla na drawot eunevA ytisrevinU
,mih dlot ehs ,llew ti gnikat saw yzuS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.knis eht ni drah gninnur retaw eht dnuof eh ereht tog eh nehw dna ,nehctik
.meht rednu egac eht fo roolf htooms drah eht leef dluoc eh tuB
.noitcelfer sih ta ylsuoiruc dereep lihP
.kcolc nehctik eht daer llits dluoc eH .yoj ho
,srosicni sih ot evolc pil reppu siH
.dehtaerb eh sa hctiwt eson nwo sih gnihctaw
,pu gnimraw saw WV dlo sih ni enigne eht elihW
,no thgil llah eht nrut t'ndid eH
.noitnetta sih thguac eye sih fo renroc eht ni gnihtemos nehT
thgil nehctik eht ffo dehctiws lihP
.kcab eht no ruf etihw dna
.tsirw sih tsniaga tlef dah eh tahw s'tahT
,roolf eht no deggard ylraen dah srae yppolf gnol siH
.deksa ehs "?pilihP ynnub wen siht llac I fi dnim ll'eh kniht uoy oD"
,egac eht edistuo rehtag ot nageb sdrib eguH
.detcepxe eh naht reimoor saw tI
.ereht tog eh nehw detresed ylraen saw ecalp ehT
,tnemtaert rof RE eht ot og dluohs eh fi derednow eH
.deb eht rednu roolf eht fo weiv doog yllausunu na dah eh noitisop siht nI
.dnuora dereep dna moor ytilitu eht otni deppets ehs sa seohs sinnet der s'yzuS dezingocer eH
.elims emosniw a saw depoh eh tahw gnireffo ,lrig eht dlot lihP
.tiaw ot dah tsuj eh woN
.erus saw eh ,erofeb keew eht tsuj meht nrow dah eH
.esaelp ,og oT"   "?og ot ro ereh rof
elbat eht ta nwod tis dluow ehs nehT
.retupmoc sih fo tuo srekcah peek ot
.hsigguls tlef eh ,eeffoc eht htiw nevE
,nesnhoJ .srM ot strohs rexob sih ni ereht gnidnats flesmih laever dna
,der tub ,tohs-doolb toN
.krow ro loohcs ta saw ehs nehw egac eht ni devil dna
,ti tuoba tbuod on saw erehT
taht dezilaer eh nehw deppots tub ,nageb eh "...oga sraey neves dna erocs ruoF"
,niaga deb fo tuo tog lihP
,no meht tup eh sa stnaptaews eht ni thguac slianeot siH
,kniw a htiw ,dias lrig eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tekcaj sih no dellup dna syek rac sih debbarg eh sa
.epacse ot woh tuo erugif t'ndluoc dna egac a edisni deppart saw eH
.slianregnif prahs esoht htiw seye sih gniregnadne saw eh taht dezilaer eh sa deppots tub
,mih was dna wodniw eht ni dekool nesnhoJ .srM fi reppots-traeh a eb dluow siht ,lleW
.ereht pleh hcum toN
.deveirter erew sderhs ylno taht os sregnif sih ni raet ecuttel eht tlef eh tub
.senots dehtooms revo gninnur maerts a ekil
,tibbar wen a yzuS gnitteg tuoba reh ksa ot detnaw eH
taht dezilaer eh ,sdnah sih dna elbat eht ta nwod gnikooL
.stigid eht neewteb pu gnitfut ruf etihw htiw ,niks knip dah tI
"?taht htiw knird ot gnihtynA"
.rennid nettogrof d'eh taht dezilaer eh ,sumatopoppih a ekil gninway
hguorht gnihcaer dna srab eht morf ecaf sih gninrut yb ti hcaer ot deirt eH
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
".wohemos nwod gnikaerb syawla era sretupmoc esohT
.swap tnorf dna seot sih no gnidnal
.rewsna ot deliaf eh fi rood nehctik eht ni flesreh tel dluow dna
.lewot repap a htiw sdnah reh depiw dna dehsaw ehs sa
.dniheb liat elttil yfoop a htiw ,semutsoc yllis rieht ni seinnub yobyalP fo sotohp esoht fo kniht mih edam tI
reh ksa dluoc eh ,owt ro emit rehtona ereht reh was eh fi ebyaM
.bus eht otni tib lihP
noitcennoc krowten sih ffo desolc dna
.gnimag dekrowten no sruoh dneps naht od ot sgniht retteb evah I
,ssenerawa sih fo egde eht delbbin
.ztiwonuB ekil stca neve eh" ,dehgual ehs ",yeH"
.derugif eh ,tseretni elttil a wohs ot truh reven tI
.rehtegot deit ylraen selkna sih htiw
.hguoht ,noitatcepxe sih naht regnarts saw deneppah taht gniht txen ehT
.stnahpele tsud dah ti
.won yldetaeper gninway saw eH
,doog llits saw eeffoc kcalb ehT
.lla retfa deb ot kcab og dluohs eh ebyaM
timda ot dah eh dna ,srab eht ot depmalc hsid llams eht ni stellep aflafla emos llits erew erehT
.ti koot yllausu eh yaw eht
ecnalab sih peek ot thguof eH
,reilrae syad owt ssalc ni saw yzuS elihw pu ti dekcip dna ,deerga d'eH
.ti devorppa d'ehs dna noitnetni sih detseggus ydaerla d'eh hguoht
.deliaf dna pu dnats srae sih ekam ot deirt eH
,retnuoc kcab eht ot denrut dna ,dias lrig eht
.tcaf ni sraey fo rebmun gnizama na
.maerd eht ni sa tsuj yrd saw yllaer
yadnuS saw worromot gniht dooG
.tsrif skeew fo elpuoc a tiaw ot mih detnaw rehtom sih tub
,lysaeW ta bew eht no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,thgin suoiverp eht dah yeht naht gnilaeppa erom hcum demees yeht wohemoS
,gniht eruS" .deddon ehS
.thguoht eh ,yrruh on os ,hguone gnisuma saw ti ,lleW
”dooF tibbaR“ saw sihT
egac eriw eht ni thguac toof sih sa flesmih ot yltfos erows dna
.gnihtyna otni gnipmub diova dluoc eh os edistuo teerts eht morf noitanimulli hguone saw erehT
.deb ot kcab tnew dna gniht elohw eht no kcab sih denrut eh
selppa delevirhs ylthgils fo lluf-flah gab citsalp a htiw gnola
.riah gnol dna seye nworb gib reh deredisnoc eh nehw ,elbirroh taht lla t'nerew hteet ehT .etad a rof
.meht fo tuo dluoc eh eciuj elttil tahw teg ot sderhs eht no ylregae dewehc eH
.puhctek fo elttob a dna
,niaga rorrim eht otni dekool lihP
.tuops eht otni dehsur ria sa dnuos gnikcus a draeh eH
.ti fo retteb thguoht tub
.ylision knard eh hcihw retaw dloc htiw ti gnillif
,ti fo retteb thguoht yletaidemmi tub ,delbmurg eh ",oot tibbar reh dna yzuS nmaD"
.thguoht eh ,yaw eht pu ycnegreme emos etiuq eb tsuM
,retaw gninnur fo dnuos eht fo lluf saw maerd txen ehT
?noitautis eht nialpxe eh dluow woH
.deid ztiwonuB retfa tibbar rehtona uoy teg dluoc eh fi em deksa eH" .dias ehs ",ees I"
.nworc eht rof gnithgif trats ot tuoba erew nrocinU eht dna noiL eht fi derednow eH
.ti tae t'ndid I dalG
.erusserp retaw oN
.sruof lla no roolf eht no saw eh ,dezilaer eh gniht txen ehT
,won teef detagnole sih no drawrof gnignirps saw eh dezilaer eh
swalc tnerapsnart gnol htiw
,dnah sih ta yltcerid kool ot rorrim morf ezag sih detfihs eH
,tibbar wen a reh gnitteg tuoba ees dna nwot ni serots tep eht kcehc ot dednetni d'eH
",gnimaerd llits m'I"
.thguoht eh ,bmuht a dah llits eh tsael tA
.raf oot gniog si sihT .hcamots lluf a no peels ot gniog dna skcans thgin etal erom oN
.enog erew srae siH
.aitnodohtro fo esruoc a evah dna
)eniratco neve spahrep(
".hguone laer s'tahT" .nwod gum eht gnittes ,dias eh ",epoN"
,oot ,elttob eht ni retaw saw erehT
,roolf eht no dloc tlef llits teef sih taht gnizilaeR
wolf eht htiw tnew
,steehs eht ni delrans saw eh taht ezilaer ot hguone denekawa eh yllaudarG
.teknalb eht rednu tog eh sa noos sa peelsa llef dna ,moordeb eht ot kcab yaw sih edam eh nehT
.deb rof eraperp ot moorhtab eht rof dedaeh dna
,tnemirepxe na sA
WV sih otni debmilc
.reiggos ylno ,repap neerg fo sderhs ekil tsuj detsat ti derugif lihP
.rotaregirfer eht morf selppa derehtiw ylthgils eht fo elpuoc a detcartxe lihP
.swodahs eht ni roolf eht no gnitser
.thguoht lihP ,thgir llA
,reh dlot eh ",sknahT"
.strohs sih ylno gniraew llits saw eh taht tcaf eht dna nesnhoJ .srM derebmemer neht dna
.dewolfrevo t'ndah ti dna raelc saw niard eht ,yletanutroF
,pu ekow eh sa neris gnissap eht otni degrem seltsihw ehT
sessalg dnuor gib esoht esol ot dedeen tsuj ehS
.strohs rexob sih ylno gniraew
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,hctiws thgil eht rof dehcaer eH
.egdirf eht ni ados teid dna reeb gniniamer eht fo kniht ot ton gniyrt
.eton a mih evael em tel tsuJ"
.yaw eht fo tuo ti gnittup fo daetsni ereht ti gnivael rof tluaf nwo sih saw tI
.yllufepoh ni dereep dna ti denepo eh tub
,nwad erofeb emitemoS
derevoc won saw eh taht ees ot ylsuoicsnoc-fles nwod dekool eh dna
,yek sih ot dleiy ot desufer esuoh eht fo rood edis ehT
”dooF tibbaR“:yojne esaelP
,tnemom a rof detatiseh lihP ".esaelp
,dehcterts dna riahc sih ni kcab denael lihP    orevO ovitlA yb
.mih tnuat ot skaeb rieht ni retaw naivE fo selttob pu gnidloh erew egac eht edistuo sdrib ehT
",doof tibbar eht dloh ot reh dlot I" .duola dias eh ",ti nmaD"
.llebrood tnorf eht draeh eh ,ruoh na tuoba retfA
.tnetsisnoc gnieb saw ti tsael ta
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.seotamot decils dna yekrut eht fo tuo yreneerg eht dekcip ylluferac eh sa
,ynnub a ekil gnippoH
.knis eht revo wodniw eht thguorht sthgilteerts eht fo wolg eht kcolb ot sneerg fo elip elttil eht dnuora sdnah sih deppuc eH
.edis mlap eht wohs ot revo ti gninrut
.melborp on os ,yadnuS saw tI
.gninialpmoc llits saw hcamots siH
.ssensuoicsnoc sih otni knas erutcip elohw eht emit sihT
,seciov owt erew erehT   .did tI
.mih ta kcab derats seye deR
.ybburg ytterp gnikool saw ti esuaceb yadretsey rehsawhsid eht ni ti tup d'eh ,haey hO .ereht t'nsaw ti
.mih ot dnah a tuo dleh dna egac eht yb nwod tlenk yzuS "!looC"
evah uoy fi llor taehw elohW" dedda neht
.deknilb dna rotinom eht evoba flehs eht no kcolc latigid eht ta detniuqs eH .seye derit sih debbur neht
.teews ylthgils dna yciuj gnihtemos no gniwehc saw eh taht dezilaer eh
,hsart eht otni sirbed eht lla ssot ot ees dluoc eh os no thgil eht nrut naht rehtaR
.dehcrap saw htuom siH
kcas repap etihw a otni bus sih deppils lrig eht emit eht yb thguoht detcartsid rehtar ni tsol saw eH
.saw ti ereht tub ,elbissopmi yllacisyhp thguoht evah dluow eh gnihtemos
.thguoht eh ,dessarrabme ro dedneffo eb ot esle eno on saw ereht dna
.sneerg dedderhs eht morf thgil elbinrecsid tub
,ereht saw ehs nehw moor s'yzuS ni esool nur dah tibbar etihw dna kcalb ybbuhc ehT
nirg dehtoot-kcub ylthgils a mih dereffo dna
.emag gniyalp elor krowten eht morf gnihtemos ekil ,thguoht eh ,demees dah tI
.tuoba yrrow ot hguone erew os ro nezod a kniht t'ndid eh tub ,suonosiop erew sdees elppa taht mih gnillet
.ti nmaD" .duola dias eh
.derewsna rehtom reh ",raed ,os kniht I"
.rennid temruog a ekil yltcaxe ton fi elbide dellems yeht
.nwod mih dewols taht selbmarb dna seniv ni delgnat gnitteg tpek tub ,maerts eht dnif ot gniyrt saw lihP
erutxet eht leef ot dnah thgir sih htiw dehcaer eh ,lla ti gnimaerd tsuj saw eh decnivnoC
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
retnuoc eht morf pu gum eeffoc sih dekcip eH
metsys reyalpitlum eht morf ffo dengis eH
tniop siht ta saw tI
,pat eht rednu ti desnir dna
,thguoht eh ,deb ot gniog erofeb thgir reeb knird ot naht retteb wonk dluohs I
.meht mirt ot eton latnem a edam eh dna
.tnorf sih nwod gum eht morf retaw dloc delbbird neht tsuj dna
,nehctik eht drawot llah eht nwod kcab gnitratS   ?ti dluow rO
.sirbed eht fo tuo dekcip ylluferac dah eh hcihw ecuttel dedderhs eht fo tsal eht gnitsat saw eh
.gnitnap saw eH .toh oot saw eh
.cinap t'nod ,thguoht eh ,thgir llA
.egac eht ot pu deppoh eod tibbar etihw dna nworb A
"?ereh t'nsi lihP hguoht neve ,won su htiw emoh mih ekat ew fi KO s'ti esoppus uoy oD
.tae ot nwod tas dna ,roiretni eht morf )esruoc fo ,etil( reeb a flesmih tog dna ,egdirf eht fo pot no egakcap eht fo tuo snikpan repap fo elpuoc a dellup lihP   .elbat eht no hciwdnas deggab sih deppord d'eh erehw nehctik eht ot denruter dna
.gnihtemos ro airetcab tnecsenimul emos eb tsuM
,sniwt esemaiS neeb evah thgim yeht taht elbat eht fo edis emas eht no rehtegot esolc os degdew erew yehT
ylneddus nehw elbat eht no sgnipparw hciwdnas eht htiw gnilddif dna maerd eht tuoba gnikniht saw lihP
.htob meht dehsinif dna
.krow rof pu teg ot evah t'ndid eh dna
.trihstaews a no dellup dna moordeb eht ot kcab tnew eH
,tsriht laer a hcneuq ot liaf dluow esoht wenk eH
.denruter maerd ehT
.nevele tsap flah saw tI
,daeherof sih debbur dna seye sih revo dnah a tup eH ".raf
.etats tneserp sih ni ti nepo llew yrev t'ndluoc eh ,lleW
.thguoht eh ,gnimaerd m'I
.hcaer sih fo tuo tsuj dnuorg eht no dial ehs hcihw
,evitcaoidar neeb dah bus sih ni ecuttel taht fi nevE
.snoitpo sih deredisnoc eh
,yek reh evah dluow rehtom sih taht wenk eH
.paeh a ni ereht gniyl tfel d'eh ecuttel eht saw tI
".keew siht bus dezis lluf yna htiw eerf er'yehT ?spihc fo gaB"
,reeb eht fo swollaws htiw desrepsretnI
.thgiew elttil a tsael ta esol ot hguone teid sih mrofer ot gniyrt saw eH
.yawa enog t'ndah dnuos retaw gnihsur eht taht dezilaer osla eh
.hcruhc htiw enod saw ehs nehw
.ysaerg ooT ?nekcihC
.won ylisae nepo ot nus gninrom eht ni hguone tuo deird dah rood eht taht depoh lihP
.ytsriht dna gnitaews
.mih ot emac noitazilaer eht nehT
.ti tuoba stbuod on dah eh tub
,ytsriht eb ot nageb eh elihw a retfA
.oga stnemom wef a snisaccom eht otni meht marc ot deliaf eh nehw thguoht d'eh sa tsuj teef tibbar llits erew hcihw
,orevO ovitlA yb
,derettum hcamots siH ".gniyl
eunevA ytisrevinU no tuo yb tnew kcurt erif a
,emit ni tuo ti erugif ll'yeht ebyaM
.eeffoc ekam ot nehctik eht ot dewap-erab kcab tnew dna
,esuoh nwo sih saw ti ,lla retfA
.thguoht eh ,gnizilaer tuohtiw ti devomer ro ,ti fo tuo delggiw d'eh wohemoS
.mom sih htiw ereht saw yzuS taht dezilaer eh dna
.tibbar laer a ekil seot sih no naht rehtar teef sih fo stalf eht no deklaw llits eh taht gniton
,mih dnuof yeht nehw eb dluow noitcaer eht tahw erus t'nsaw eH
.lla ta gnikool dab t'nsaw ehS
.uaerub eht revo rorrim eht ot dereggats eh ,ees dluow eh tahw gnidaerD
tuhs rood egac eht deppans retsis sih sa
,moordeb eht ot kcab deklaw eH
.hguoht ,reppils eht otni leeh sih teg t'ndluoc eH
tsuj eh taht reeb gniniamer eht htiw llew os dnelb ot demees
.daeh sih koohs eh dna ,deksa ehs
,sehcnuah sih no pu gnittis ni dedeeccus ylno tub
.maerd ddo na morf lihP denekawa neris eht dna
,teef erab sih no nehctik eht ot llah eht nwod deddap eh oS
.semit ynam od ztiwonuB nees dah eh sa
,mih dniheb elknit rood eht tel eH
.sserddA grubsytteG eht gniticer deirt lihP
.won deb eht sa llat sa ylno saw eh rednow oN .thguoht eh ,ho hU
.gnihtemos ro krow ot ni dellac neeb evah tsum eH
,elbat eht ta niaga nwod tas lihP
",sknaht ,oN" dias tub ,detpmet saw lihP
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,wap a yltcnitsid saw tI
.emoh kcab thgiarts dedaeh dna
?won klat neve eh dluoC
.rehtaew pmad ni did semitemos ti sa
.pol larutan a saw eh ebyam os ,rehtie namuh a sa srae sih elggiw ot elba neeb reven d'eh ,neht tuB
.srae pol ekil dekool taht sdiarb yvaeh ni gnuh riah thgiarts tsomla reH
,yllufetarg knard eh dna
.thguoht eh ,drieW
,seinnub tsud evah t'ndid tI
.emoh tog eh nehw rood tnorf eht edisni ti tfel neht
,maerd a erew siht fI
.thguoht eh ,no denrut ti tfel evah tsum eH
.enituor lamron a saw tahT
dias eh ,flesmih revo teknalb eht gnilluP
.yks eht ni wodaem gib eht ot revo dessap yllanif dah ztiwonuB taht mih dlot dah moM sih ,erofeb keew eht ylnO
,gnitniaf ro gnimaercs fo daetsnI
.ti htiw depparw dah lrig eht elkcip eht otni tib dna bus eht dehsinif eH
.thgil nehctik eht no hctiws ot rehtob t'ndid lihP
dezilaer tub ,peels ot kcab og ot deirt dna denway lihP
elbat eht morf pu tog eH
.elbissopmi demees siht tub
.yrd os erew yeht ,demees ti ,spil sih esolc neve t'ndluoc eH
.keew siht eciwt taht dah ,haN ?azziP
"...tub ,nuf neeb s'tI .siht morf pu ekaw ot emit ,KO"
.swodniw gnirobhgien
,oot ereht erew strohs rexob siH
.gninaelc emuser ot htolc reh pu dekcip dna
,gnipparw repap dexaw eht no kcatsyah elttil a ni ecuttel eht gnivaeL
.derats dna rood eht fo renroc eht dnuora denael rehtom siH   ".eno etihw etuc A
.siht enod evah t'ndluow ti
,noonretfa ylrae eht ni emitemos yb pots ylbaborp dluow moM siH
.llew sa selos eht enimaxe ot roolf eht morf pu meht gnikcip
,lleW .eeffoc fo sthguoht dah eh dna
.thguoht eh ,ffuts gnilevel siht fo hguonE
eht no sthgil ycnegreme gnissap eht fo snoitcelfer eht ees dluoc eh erehw nehctik eht ni tub
.won ynnub a tog s'lihP"
.deretne lihP sa delgnij rood eht no lleb eht nehw pu kool neve t'ndid dna
.eton a mih evael dna
,pu gniht elohw eht dekcip dna
.tsafkaerb utpmorpmi na rof od thgim yeht dediced eh dna
.dnuos a fo elffuns gnizeehw a tub tuo gnimoc saw gnihton
.thguoht lihP ,evitcartta rehtar saw ehs ,hteet eht rof tpecxE .deksa lrig eht
.ylediw denway lihP
",lla retfa gnihtemos rof doog si doof tibbar sseug I ,zeeJ"
,teef sih ot teg ot deirt lihP
,gnieb meht derebmemer eh naht retteb hcum erew selppa ehT
.lla dna sdees ,meht fo htob eta eh dna
.gab hciwdnas dna srepap dexaw eht ta gnireep ,elbat eht revo denael eH
.detsal dah ztiwonuB reh gnol woh s'taht tub
dnah reh ni gar pmad a htiw esac rotaregirfer eht dniheb morf pu emac lrig retnuoc emit thgin ehT
,flesmih dlot lihP
,esruoc fo dna ,ytiniffaruF
.srosicni etihw fo riap gnimrahc a wohs ot detrap ylgnihctef saw pilerah wen siH
eh tahw tub ,niaga rehtael rae sih fo
.nehctik eht otni ti yrrac ot egac ytpme eht pu dekcip dna
,gnittis saw egac dlo s'ztiwonuB erehw
.erèirred dednuor reh evoba thgir wob elbuod a ni deit saw norpa reh taht deciton lihP
.sedis eht ta nwod gnignah erew dna daeh sih fo pot eht ot devom dah yeht ,tiaw ,oN
,gnimaerd saw eh decnivnoc llitS
.gniyl ro loof a rehtie si evitcidda t'nsi ffuts taht smialc ohw enoyna" ,flesmih ot dias eh ",nmaD"
.ti etavargga yllautca thgim dna
,dlo sraey neetxis eb ot evil yllamron t'ndid seinnub erus saw eH
,etunim a retfa meht dnuof ,deb eht rednu snisaccom fo riap a rof tlef lihP
.dloc tlef teef s'lihP
,gniraew neeb d'eh trihstaews egnaro eht fo eveels eht ees dluoc eH
.trihstaews yttar a gniraew ynnub retsaE na ekil dekool eh
,yawevird eht ssorca nehctik sih decaf wodniw moordeb esohw
.siht fo tseb eht ekam ot yaw a eb ot sah erehT
thguoht gniggan emoS
,thguoht eh ,snoitalupop tneduts rof denut seitinema htiw sesupmac egelloc rof ssendoog knahT
roloc tnereffid a fo esroh a si ohw
tniaf yrev a yletinifed saw erehT
.ecuttel ni was elpoep tahw dootsrednu reven d'eh tub ,seotamot eht dnim t'ndid eH
,htuom reh ni ecuttel fo fael a gniyrrac saw ehS
.hciwdnas eht rof 73.3$ eht revo dednah eh sa suoutriv leef ot deirt dna
,delgnatnesid ecnO
.llew ylriaf mih detarelot dah rehtom rieht os ,xob rettil sih gnisu tuoba suoiditsaf etiuq saw tub sgniht gnilbbin rof ytisneporp a dah eh dna
",gnimaerd llits m'I"
eht morf gnimoc saw tI
.deb eht no elgnat a ni gniyl ,stnaptaews yarg sih dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,bus eht depparwnu eH
.ni flesmih tel ot ti dekcolnu dna
,gnimaerd t'nsaw eh yltnedivE
.tsirw sih tsniaga depard ytevlev dna tfos gnihtemos tlef eh nehT
.retaw fo knird a teg dna ssip ot moorhtab eht rof gnidaeh
.hciwdnas eht elbmessa ot evolg citsalp elbasopsid a no gnillup
,rehto eht neht dna toof eno ta
".eno eht eb tsum siht sseug I
,orevO ovitlA yb ”dooF tibbaR“
,rehtegot resolc neve devom dah htoob renroc eht ni elpuoc eht taht gniciton
.deb eht fo egde eht revo gnilgnad
,eod a saw ti wenk eh woh erus t'nsaw eH
mlac yats ot deirt eh os
.egac eht otni debmilc eH .nepo rood
,pu gniworg rehto hcae htiw thguof d'yeht lla roF
.retnuoc eht no nwod ti tes dna
,thgil neddus eht ni derettilg reeb dna ados fo snac nrolrof wef A
.eerf teg ot elggurts a ot gnidael
.edistuo daor eht no gnissap enigne erif rehtona raeh ot hguone pu ekow eh taht
.yad eht ni retal elihw a rof peels yllaer ot hguone derit eb d'eh ebyaM
,dnah reh no daeh sih gnibbur dna
.ruf etihw ywons htiw
.dellac ehs "!moM ,yeH"
.hsart eht otni meht dessot dna
.pu teg llew sa thgim ,KO
pu denrut dna yawevird sih fo tuo dellup eH
.ecuttel dedderhs htiw ti dedaol dah lrig eht ,snoitcurtsni sih fo etips ni taht dnuof dna
,elbat eht no nac reeb eht dna sgnipparw eht gnivaeL
?ssol eht no gnidoorb morf reh peek ot yawa egac eht gnikat dnim eh dluow tub
,wenk eh ,ytpme ylraen saw egdirf ehT
.ti eerf ot redro ni sedutitta noxaS-olgnA ecitcarp ot mih gnicrof
.no meht tup ot detrats dna
,trihstaews eht erew erehT
reh drawot gnippoh tsiser t'ndluoc lihP
.sesiri knip htiw
htuom sih esuaceb retaw fo knird rehtona teg ot pat eht no denrut dna
.tep reh rof noitceffa peed reh detcepser dna retsis sih fo dnof saw lihP
tub knis eht no tpek yllamron eh ssalg eht rof dehcaer dna dehsulf eH
.meht fo tnorf ni spuc eeffoc citsalp htiw htoob renroc a ni tas elpuoc enO
?gninrom eht ni owT
.pohs eht ni lrig eht tuoba gnikniht llits ,ffo ti hsilop ot nageb eh
",ecuttel dna oyam eht dloh ,bus yekrut decils eht ekil d'I"
.tsacdop goD fo ecioV ehT
,dedeeccus tsomla dna ,leef yb ti barg ot
.emitnaem eht ni gnihtyna tuohtiw og ro evrats t'now I tsael ta tuB .ton ebyam ro
.yaw gnigaruocne na ni ebut latem eht tsniaga gnilttar srosicni detagnole sih
ylgniveilebnu derats lihP
,edistuo yks eht otni gnipeerc saw yarg gninrom dloC
.thgil hsineerg a htiw gnirekcilf saw ti raews dluoc eH
.ruoh na tuoba ni yb emoc dluohs moM
.doof fo hcraes ni nehctik eht otni dereggats eh dna
,niaga dehcterts dna pu doots eh sA
,sraey rof tibbar tep a tpek dah retsis s'lihP
.pu ekaw yllanif dluow eh nehw derednow eh
.suolucidir saw taht tub ,neknurhs dah niksreed eht fi sa saw tI
,stnemele eht morf deretlehs retteb saw hcihw ,rood tnorf eht ot dnuora deklaw lihP
.rehtona eno ot gniltsihw dna ylirgnuh mih gnieye
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.gnorw saw tahw tuo erugif ot thgil edisdeb eht no denrut eh yllaniF
nac ytpme eht dna sgnipparw hciwdnas eht derehtag eh emit sihT .duola dias eh
.sreksihw tnerapsnart gnol yb decalper ,enog saw ehcatsuom siH
",neht thgin doog a evaH"
.sserttam eht fo level eht ot seye sih gnirb ot hguone gnihcterts
.teknalb eht rednu morf tuo gnikcits eb tsum yehT
",dereviled tsuj hctab hserF"   ".eno
.retaw on saw ereht tub
,gnihtemos ni thguac slianeot sih tub ffo teknalb eht kcik ot deirt eH ?gnitnaP
,reyrd dna rehsaw eht ot txen moor ytilitu eht otni egac eht tup eH
.dnah a ton saw rorrim eht ni was
,moor ytilitu eht otni deppoh eH
rebmucuc denirb eht fo etsat cilrag ytlas eht tub ,esoht tae yllausu t'ndid eH
,deppird eeffoc eht elihW
.niaga pu ekow eh nehw wollip sih otno thgir wodniw moordeb eht ni gninihs saw nus ehT
.rood nehctik eht ot ti gniyrrac