,relevart wollef ruoy
.NGISLLAC htiw
,airetcab ,setalucitrap ,trid ,ffonur lacimehc ton dnA
,yrassecen ,sseltroffE
,”niaR“   yojne esaelP
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,anueL yb
suoiciled eb tsael ta dluohs tI
,anueL yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
”niaR“ saw sihT       ?I t’nac yhW
doog etsat ot niar eht tnaw I  anueL yb meop a
yks eht morf gnillaf ,citehtnys dna larutan ,eramthgin elbirroh yreve
etercnoc dega hguorht gnitsrub htworg hserF
,cirbaf otni sknis tI
ti stpecca dlrow larutan eht ,dlrow ruO
gab dlo ym fo ffo gnileeP sraeY tneps evaH I gnifoorpretaw eht secreip
.ytiniffaruf rieht no
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
tsiyasse oediv a sa skrow ohw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
esion tnasaelp otni dnelb lla airetcab dna trid dna snosioP lufituaeb
floWcaM boR si sihT
,emitnaem eht ni noitcif trohs setirw dna