"?thgin tsal tar a eb ot dehsiw uoy em llet annog uoY .haeY"
.aloL ot pu kcab gnicnuob erofeb knird eht ot deppord seye sih neht ,yllanif em ta dekool yttaR
".yug raluger a saw I ,yadretseY .saw I rO
.evila saw eh elihw pots ot esnes hguone dah ssakcaj eht tsael tA
.yas t'ndluoc I ,ezis taht recnuob a ssim dluoc enoyna woh hguoht
.dedne siht woh ekil ot gniog t'nsaw I gnileef a dah I tub ,ssendriew rof net pot eht ni kcab mih tup gnihsiW ".parC"
,sruls laicar nezod a flah htiw ecnetnes taht dehsinif evah dluoc eH ".ton
,neht derepmihw eH ".haeY"
.smaerd ym fo namow eht teem ot dehsiw I"
,mra ym no dednal wap siH "!tiaW"
namuh dlab ,raluger a erew uoy oS"
.tniop taht ta elbatirahc oot gnileef t'nsaw I tub ,knird laer a mih dereffo evah dluohs I ebyaM
.mih no etsaw ot emit erom yna evah 't'ndid I
.elzzum sih ni elknirc a htiw em ta dna ,snortap ym ta
.em no swap yal ot naht retteb nwonk evah d'eh ro ,etarepseD
.elacs gnitseretni ym no sehcton wef a deppord eh dna ,saedi fo tuo nur d'I ".emahS" ".oN"
.mih ot gniklat em tpek ytisoiruc tub ,yhtapmys ym htiw gnola gniyd saw ecneitap yM ".seod eh teb I"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ereh ni taht fo regnad yna s'ereht taht toN
"?deb erofeb driew gnihtyna tae ro knird uoy diD"
”staR“:yojne esaelP   .moc.iluapsecnarf//:ptth no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoY lmth.koobe-
.yltnerappa ,seno detogib nevE
.namuh a ma I naem I"
.won net pot eht ot resolc yaw sih dekrow d'eh tuB .rab a nur I
.ot detnaw eh ees dluoc I dna
.reffo ot sah ytic eht stnedor suoiroton tsom eht fo emos fo lluf elbat a ees d'uoy ,renroc raf taht ni revo dekool uoy fi
.renroc kcab eht ni egats eht drawot yaw reh gniknils tac esemaiS eht no erew seye lla dna
.aloL evivrus t'ndluoc krej tahT
"?raelcun gnihtyna raen ro bal a ni krow t'nod uoY"
.tnega AED a nees tsuj d'eh ekil ecalp eht dnuora gnitrad dna srecuas sa egral
".nam ,ssenisub a si sihT"
.taorht sih fo kcab eht ni sesion gnikohc tfos edam tar-
.dnuoH gnilranS eht dellac si tnioj eht yhw yltcaxe mih dewohs dna pil reppu ym delruc I
".tar a eb ot desoppus ton m'I"
,reywal doog a rof esnefed ysae nA
.larutannU .drawkwA .ffitS
.nam-tar ot htraE
,og meht dehctaw dna thgilemiL eht kcab dessot I
".yddub ,esolc neve toN" ".uoy ekiL" ".derruF"
.gnikcinap dehsinif tsuj d'eh esuac' ebyam dna mih llik annog saw I wenk eh esuac' ebyaM .yllanif
"?naem uoy od tahW"
,nwod tohs eht tes I nehW
.emit eht lla nioj siht ni star tog ev'eW
.swalc reh ni liat s'yttaR dah aloL
,smaerd sih fo namow eht saw ehs fi tub
.tnereffid saw tar sihT
.hsiw cigam a ro sesruc ,nosiop ,snoitop eb t'naC"
ta derats eH
.won devom liat sih woh eciton tub pleh t'ndluoc I dnA
".ot dnet ot sremotsuc tog I
oduesp eht elihw rehto eht ot wap eno morf ti gnittab
.srettam otni mih gnirb ot dah I nehw desirprus demees llits yehT
.tseb eht dah I dna
.traeh derruf a ynam deniur dah taht elims a dna
.allef ,derebmuntuo yaW .haeY
"?yltnecer ffo enoyna ssip uoY
.knird eht ta derats dna em etisoppo deppots tar ehT
.tnemom eht rof tsael tA
.su no seye sih dah eh erus ekam ot ni dekcehc ,eoJ ot deddon I ".nwod ti peeK"
,yad fo emit eht tnatnuocca dlab a nevig evah t'ndluow aloL .yawyna ,em roF
.dias I ekil ,gniht tsedriew eht ton s'tI "?os taht sI"
"?hsiw cigam yas uoy diD"
seye tac reh otni derats ,reh
...aerf yna wonk neve t'nod I ,naem I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitcerid ym ni keep a gnikaens reh thguac I tub
...etarepsed laer saw eh .haeY
"?yug gib ,rof hsiw uoy did tahW"
.ti ekil leef uoy fi namuh yalp uoy pleh nac ohw rotcod evisnepxe laer a s'ereht raeh I" .em derob d'eh woN
"?gnivil a rof od uoy od tahW"
"?tar a er'uoy won dna ,yug raluger a eb ot desoppus er'uoY"
".siht ekil pu ekow I" "...neht dna
.truoc ni retaw dloh t'ndid thgilemiL gnivres ,poc a saw allef siht esac ni tsuJ
.niaga liat sih rof dehcaer dna mih ta seye neerg deknilb ehS
".seitriht ym ecnis dlab neeB
,eoJ tuo tniop ot aedi doog a syawla saw tI ".rood
.rab eht dniheb sessalg ytpme eht elttar ot hguone duol derrup ehS
.rab a otni deklaw tar A
eno rehtona mih deruop I
.tib eno erac t'ndluow yttaR
.sehsiw htiw wonk reven uoY
".flesmih ot speek fo dnik eh tub ,krow ta syug uoy fo eno s'erehT .derruf
… .tar a eb ot nrob saw eh ekil tsuJ
dna ssalg tohs naelc a pu dellup I dna ,hcaer ni saw taht kcehc kciuq enO
.aedi doog a si rotcod taht ebyaM
.rab eht rof dedaeh dna
.snoitop cigam tuo seluR"  "?yhW .oN"
.od ot tahw wonk t'nod tsuJ I .yrroS"
.uoy dlot I .elbuorT ".hu-I"
,rab eht dnuora dekool dna thgilemiL dnoces eht demmals eH
.yaw ruo dekool sraluger eht fo wef a dna
?neht tahw eb ot desoppus er'uoY"
.bmud laer dna
?tar-denrut-tnatnuocca dlab raluger a dna
.ogniB .staC .ytisoiruC
og tel eH ".taht naem t'nod I"
.ecalp eht nwo I .wonk dluohs I
.efas knird uoy ,tnioj siht ni knird uoY .oN
hgih pu ,gnorw lla liat sih dleh eh dnA
.sgod ekil t'ndid ehs dab ooT
.cinap dias taht seye sih revo ezalg a dah tnedor gnikool dliw siht tuB
,devirra dah tnemniatretne s'thgin ruO
.emad a ni tnaw d'uoy esle gnihtyna dna ,ssalc ,elyts dah ehS
.pord a gnillips tuohtiw kcab ti dessot dna tohs eht koot eh tub ,koohs swap siH
,won neve dna ,syob sih htiw tahc a rof yadrutaS yreve ereh ni yenohaM sreksihW tog eW
.laer rof riah evah neve t'nod I"
.pu gid dluoc eh noitanalpxe revetahw rof detiaw dna
".tnatnuocca na m'I"
.reh fo strap thgir eht lla degguh dna deremmihs sserd der elttil reh yaw eht dna aloL morf eralg eht gnirongi ,thgilemiL rehtona deruop I
.gnihtemos ro nossel a nrael ot ereh saw yug eht ebyaM
.regnirred ycnegreme ym ot txen thgir ti
"?huh ,melborp ruoy rof noitanalpxe elbissop yna tuo delur ev'ew kniht I"
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,yrautcnas ym dniheb noitisop otni dils I emit eht yB
.laed eht delaes hgis siH
.kaeps ot os grebeci eht pihc t'ndid tar a ton s'eh gnimialc tar a tub
.decnad sreksihw gnol sih dna daeh sih koohs yttaR ".oN" .emit yrevE
,iluaP secnarF yb ”staR“ saw sihT
.dnoces a rof tsuJ
.rab eht ni esle enoyna ro ...flesreh eldnah t'ndluoc aloL taht toN
rab eht morf yawa nam-tar eht del ehs tub
.tsrif ereht tog sserd der eht ni yttik eht tub ,rab eht drawot kcab derepmacs I .yaw oN
,gnaf a desopxe elims reH
.niaga dworc eht dekcehc I
.oot ,gnitanicsaf erew sehsiw thguoht yltnerappa ,aloL
"?knird s'esle enoemos knird rO ?yella na ni namow dlo egnarts a morf ydnac yna ekat uoy did naem I"
.elcric yzal a ni rab eht depiw dna gar ym tuo dellup I "?os taht sI"
.yddub yeH" .etal ooT
,oot liat s'yttaR deppord ehS
.sesruc tuoba woH" .gnihtoN
.tar a nrob saw ohw yug a ekil tol a gnikool ,ecaf sih revo swap sih debbur
.ton m'I ...a ton m'I
.lla ta uoy fo eno eb ot desoppus ton m'I naem I"
.yttaR morf rewsna oN
.oot egats eht no erew seye siH
"?gnihtemos rof hsiw did uoy tuB" ".yltcaxe toN"
.tcefreP .denworf aloL ".aedi
.yllaer ,laed a fo gib taht t'nsaw tI
.reh peek dluoc eno siht ebyaM
.dab enog eciuj tiurf yllacisab saw tI
.sseug I ,sklof no tceffe taht sah aloL
.niaga liat sih tuo dekcehc I dna ,kcab emac kool yzarc eht nehT
,aloL no dexif erew seye tar siH ".haeY .eruS"
.yllaer enod er'ew kniht I
.devlos saw yretsym eht tsael tA
.did esle ydobon ,yletanutrofnU .dehgual I
.toidi siht naht reidahs gnihtyna rof rab eht dennacs dna walc a htiw nihc ym dehctarcs I ".snoitop
.egats eht yb pu thgir taes a ekat tar derruf ylwen eht dehctaw
,sremotsuc ym fo eno fo htuom eht fo tuo emoc ot gniht tsedriew eht saw taht yas dluoc I hsiw I woN ".tar a ton m'I"
.yletelpmoc nalp ym deliops dna htuom sih denepo eh tub
,dluoc derruf ynam toN
.ezis sih flah yug a ffo me' elots d'eh ekil dekool sehtolc siH
revoL maerD pu depparw ehs nehw ekil did ehs saw ti tahw derebmemer I
".fo wonk I taht toN"
.syawedis seye tar gib sih dellor eH " .wonk uoY .haeY"
kcut ot rednu dehcaer neht dna gar a htiw retnuoc eht depiws I
.tuoba deirrow saw I yttaR saw tI .oN
.yug eht morf gnihtaol-fles naht gnitseretni erom tol a gnihtemos detcepxe d'I ".netsiL"
deb ot tnew uoy nehw
,thgir t'nerew seye sih sretrats rof lleW ?wonk I d'woH
.T lotipac a htiw elbuort saw eh ,ffo tsriF
"?haey-Y" .yawyna deirt I ".yddub
tes tsrif eht hguorht rab eht tsniaga denael eH
.rood eht yb revo eoJ ekil raeb 'lo gib a ebyaM ?regit A
taht deliaw eH "!wonk I"
.yawa pord t'ndid tub dexaler pirg siH
.niaga elbuorT .stnedoR
,ti htiw deyalp ehS
.erehwyreve hguorht gnikeep ruf dna dekoorc pu denottub trihS
.niaga dnuora decnalg eH
"?deneppah tahw oS"
"?tohs rehtona tnaw uoY"
"?yttaR ,thgir lla uoY"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.koobe-dednabsid/201p/erots/moc.snoitacilbuplaog.www//:sptth snoitacilbuP laoG morf seires aitnepreS eht fo rohtua
iluaP secnarF yb
.detnemmoc meht fo rehtien
.yllaer ,ecnahc a dah reven loof rooP .tsoL
.syawedis fo tros ,nosrep yzarc a ekil deddon eH ".haeY" ".derruF"
yrots s’yadot dna
.snortap ym fo straeh eht otni yaw reh derrup dna denoorc aloL elihw
ssenkraDnihtoM/moc.rettiwt//:sptth iluaP secnarF yb ”6315021/weiv/moc.yrrufos.www//:sptth  staR“   si
tsirw nwo reh fo kcilf tfed a htiw
.rab elohw eht gnikrow ot kcab tnew dna retnuoc eht no thgilemiL driht a tfel I
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
".siht ekil pu ekow tsuj I"
.edis ot edis dna woL
.rof saw liat a tahw wonk t'ndid eh ekil ,ffits dna
,esruoc fo dnA  .elbuorT
.swalc fo kcirp eht tlef I dna ,ruf ym ni sregnif gnol
.liat dlab eht dekorts dna derrup aloL .staR ".smaerd
.tac taht ,tca taerG
.rab ym rof thgiarts dehcram ti
.esuac tsol a saw eh wonk ot em rof hguone gnol
.egnar otni elbma ot deganam eh erofeb thgilemiL a yug eht deruop