.’niteem ylimaf a dellac dna
,deciton ev’seinop rehtO
.ssenisub ref taerg eb annog si tuo ’nihcnarb tub ,taerg s’ellivynoP .’nihtemos atno yllaer rey kniht hA ’na ,nisuoC ,rettel rey tog hA“
.eno rehtona revo dellup eH ”.eponnN“
”.sercA elppA teewS ta tae hA ’na ,caM giB m’hA“
.sucof attuo dna ni dils seye siH ”.’nisihcnarF“
,selppa ruo esitrevda at—
.rehtegot nwot ni yrekab yreve morf eip a hguorht tnew eW ”.eponnN“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,nrubearB morf draeh hA tsaL ”.hoooooO“ .em a’llaaaaa ot
.me‘ fo sdaol ,seip dah elbat ehT
dnuora neht dna ,em ta pu dna
.decnuob dna …em atni dewolp eh
.elbmur yreve ta depmuj dworc eht dna
...gnitae detrats I ,oS
’sercA elppA teewS ta staE caM giB‘
.redic ’a gek a ’na
em hsup at detnaw eh yllausu ’nA
,ti tuob‘ tennob reh ni eeb a dah JA retsis ham tuB .htuom ham otni ekacpuc detsorf-elbuod a deppop ehs dna
.nigram ediw a yb ”noillats tseggib“ no dael ham werg hA tub
.teef sih no elbbow ’na ruls at ’nitrats saw eH
.tsevrah eht erofeb nepir ot selppa eht ref ’nitiaw erew ew ’na
.em ta kool gnol ,doog a tig enoyreve tel ’na tuo delbmur hA
.’nihtemos eb yllaer tsum ew
,nwot ni seirekab tnereffid morf sexob ni emac yehT
’nikop ,peed ni ti knas dna ylleb ham no thgir fooh a detnalp ehS .tuoba klat at detnaw JA tahw saw taht ’nA .sneppah taht
,gnisitrevda eerF .dias yeht
.em ref srood eht denediw yeht taht hguone doog saw ssenisub yltnerappA
nwot ’a elddim eht ni egats a pu ’nittes pu dnuow eW
.redic ruo ’na ,seidoog dekab ruo
.’ninthgil sa kciuq nwod ti delbbog dna eip eht otni ecaf ham deffuts hA
,ria aht ni pu raer taf
?ereh siht tuoba tahW“
.tah sih ffo dehsurb dna pu flesmih dekcip eH
”!nwot ni yrekab tseb eht morf s’ti ’na ,elppa s’ti
,ydob siht ref dekrow hA ’nA !esroh a ma
.ecitsuj em od ot mees t’nod noitalleppa eht ,yletal tub
,mrots a pu ’nilworg saw hcamots haM
.htaerb a koot hA emit yreve selppa detsat hA
,emit tsrif eht ref esuaceb ti s’taht kniht at ekil hA .taht ekil hA
,dias eniM
.pohs deklat ew ’na nwod mih tup hA ,yllautnevE
”.puyeE“ ”.me‘ fo ynnelP
,elcsum gnorts dna edih tfos s’em a’hcni yrevE .hsulp m’hA .gib tsuj ton m’hA
kcab ajdeen yeht ’nod—!cih—nisuoC“
,dnuora noillats tsegnorts eht llits saw hA
,seenk rey tsap nwod sgnah ylleb rey ’na ,redluohs at redluohs ’nidnats seinop eerht yna sa ediw sa rey nehW
,eip a s’tI !dloheB“
”?puyeE“ ”...hu ,uoy ,nisuoC“
,yobdooG ydduB yb ”suoicileD deR“ saw sihT
,detsat ’nihtyreve doog woh seinop wohs ’na dnuor‘ og ot dah tsuj hA oS
”?pu ti peek annog ooy
.seihcnum ni em tpek yeht sa gnol sa sngis eht pu peek me‘ tel hA
.em ’a tnorf ni elbat eht no ti tup eH
pu deyats hA ’n‘ nrubearB ,thgin tahT
,lleW“ .segde eht dnuor‘ detsorf ragus ’a dat a tsuj htiw ’na ,ykalf ,nworb-nedloG
!ereh tuo ssenzib taerg ’niod rey tuB“ ”.puyeE“ ”?mraf aht ta
,yobdooG ydduB yb ”suoicileD deR“
,’niyas erew seinoP
.etsaw ot og seip ’seirekab rehto meht lla ’nittel tniop on t’nerew ereht dediced hA
.skeehc taf kcab hsup ot dah elims ham ’na ,thguoht eht ta delims hA
!dnegel lacol a s’tI
,rood eht a’edis rehto eht no ’nA
,me‘ tsniaga sserp I ’na ,me‘ tsap redluohs I sa neht tub
.erutats dednapxe sih at yldneirf yltcaxe t’nerew rood esuohloohcs eht taht
.skcoltef ym tsniaga dehsurb dna ,dilos deffuts saw tug yM
?tsrif asoolelppA yrt annaw uoy d’yhw—
er’woH .’niyub peek at me‘ tnaw ay fi ,ay ees attog seinop—!pru—’niyas m’hA !si caM giB ohw swonk ynopon n’fi
,no tnuoc syawla n’c hA gniht eno s’erehT
,selppa tog yeht ,dlot tog hA
…daer ot ikahK rof ysae s’ti os stnedni on htiw lairA stp61 si siht dna ,thgin ymrots dna krad a saw tI   .ezis tsev rehtona pu enog d’eh
.redic eht nwod deplug eh dna
.nees reve d’ehs hsur noonretfa tseb eht reh evag
yrots tnereffid a eb d’worromoT
,yletal hguone netfo taht tlef s’eH
,esruoC‘ .em tsniaga pu ’nihsurb htob snoillats n‘ seram tog hA
.edisni kcuts dna deffuts fles taf sih a’erom steg ylno eh tub
”!nisuoc ,ereht ,yeH“
.caM em sllac ynopyreve tub ,hsotnIcM m’hA
,’nihtyna ekil ’ninnirg
,lil a tsurc eht delbbin ,ti deffins hA
,emit eht lla airtseuqE ’nivas tuo kcajelppA retsis ham htiW
,elppa yna sa yvruc ’na ynihs ’na der ,llor kciht ,gib A
,nosaes wols eht saw ti ,yawynA
,sserpxE eht ffo tig hA sa noos
.ecno ref em’t noitnetta yap’t ynopyreve detnaw tsuj ha sseug ha
dnatsrennu hA kniht t’nod hA tuB
.noitcerid yreve ni
”?yrgnuh uoy t’niA
.edih sih tsniaga emarf doow eht ’niciton ylerab ,enut a ’niltsihw ,esaelp ay sa ysae ni sturts eh ,si rehtorb gib taht sa gnortS
.gum sih fo tsal eht kcab dekconk eH
”.yhtlaeh …kool uoY“
:dias ’na ,spil ham dekcil hA
.eromyna eciton neve t’nseod eh
,kcuts flesham tig d’hA taht hguone doog s’yrekab eht fi
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,lausu eb ot ’nitteg saw sa ,saw hA
”.ereh siht si tfel tog ew lla ,nisuoc
.erom on dehsup ylisae os ton m’hA
rood reh ni kcuts tneps hA ’ninrom eht em dlot ekaC .srM
,krow tnurg laer od ot dah hA erofeb og at shtnom dah eW
rehcaetloohcs a erutcip neht ’nA .stiaw eh dna ,ksed reh drawot koob s’retsis sih ssot at seirt dna shgis eH
!sercA elppA teewS ta stae caM giB
hA esuaceb esroh a ekil tae lliw hA
.dehsuh dworc ehT
,dias ’na ,retnuoc aht at pu deilleb ,teerts aht nwod regruB yaH eht at tnew hA neht ’nA !yako dias hA ’nA
”!rediC !selppa deidnaC
kcab tog hA nehw serohc lausu ham evah llits
.qsEyobdooGydduB/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf ta ,ytiniffAruF no yrellag a sah ohw
,eip elppa na ni nwod eson
.morf emac taht erehw erom saw ereht dias ’na ,srettirf elppa a’esac a em tnes ekaC .srM neht tub ,dias hA
.robal ham fo stiurf rehto eht ’nitsevrah yb flesham gniyojne saw hA os
,uoy llet emmel ,yob ’nA
.flesham taert ll’hA ,ffo m’hA nehw ’na ,drah krow hA .ecno ref ta derats eb at diarfa t’nia hA ’na ,sknaht n‘ esaelp ,hcnul rof esaelp llew nrad hA tahw evah ll’hA ’na ,gnorts m’hA ,gib m’hA
.hguorht trap tsediw sih nettog neve t’nsah eh
wonk ll’ynopyreve
,eip eht ta nwod dekool eH
,dehsulb dna ,dehcleb eH
...reh ref gnitiaw selppa neerg gib owt dnif at ssecer morf ylrae kcab ’nimoc
.ecnatsnir’f ,srooD
.’nihtemos evah at dah yeht
,enim ’a dneirf a ot lla’y ecudortni annaw hA ’nA !yad asoolelppA lufitooy-eeeeb siht no em ’ninioj ref seinop uoy lla knaht annaw hA“ .daeh sih sesu eh nehw ,erehwyna og ot enoyna teg nac nrubearB
,ay llet hA .hsup a ref ’nA
!em tikooL ,dias enim ’nA
!eseht ekil selppa yna nees t’nia uoY
”.ereH staE caM giB“
,em a’niward liL
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.noitnetta ’nitteg detrats hA
.mih ta eip elppa na dehsup ’na
* * * ?ahct’nod ,oot od uoY
,lliw ay fi erutciP
.em atni thgir guns mih tel ’na ,guh gib a ref ni mih dellup hA ”.puyeE“
,sercA elppA teewS morf sredro asoolelppA neve fi ’nA
”.redic rey hsiniF
...der ydaerla t’nerew skeehc ym fi
.asoolelppA ’nitisiv pu dnuow hA woh s’taht oS
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.kcab skool eh ’na
.em rof thgir ’nimoc’a syawla s’eh ’na
,ffo wohs ot sehcni attoL
”!hsotnIcM giB ,nisuoc ym
,sgel dnih gnorts sih htiw sehsup eH
,wodniw aht ni ngis lil a sah renroC ebucraguS
.’niworg s’ti esruoC‘“
,sknalf sih dnuor‘ hcnip a sleef eh ,ylneddus litnU
.tog hA ecnahc yreve flesham ’niffuts shtnom tneps d’hA
.dab lla t’nia ti tuB
,flesham egrog srettirf ot hguone htiw evael llits dna ,tuo dils eb ot detiaw hA elihw kcans
.eno tsal yreve nwod denrut hA yhw derednow dworc ehT
.nepo niatruc eht dellup eH
,thgieh ham tuo dellif hA ecnis reve ,caM giB
”suoicileD deR“   yojne esaelP
.syadawon ruof at resolc m’hA ’na ,yawyna eman d’c ay seinop owt yna n’reggib saw hA .ffo ti ’niwohs pleh nac hA taht toN
.smrof redro attuo neht dna ,selpmas attuo nar eW
.emarfrood eht revo mih drawot tuo seglub
...tub ,pu ekat hA ecaps hcum woh a’tnuocca no yltrap s’ti
nepo ’nignah saw htuom sih esuaceb ,emit tsrif eht ref em was yllaer eh ekil dekool eh
.ffo meht wohs at em esu annaw yeht semitemos dna
.em htiw thguorb hA eip a tuo dellup nrubearB ,yllaniF
,emit tsrif eht reF
srevotfel ’a hsats ham ’niyojne
,emit siht tub ,sthgis eht em wohs ’na nwot dnuor‘
.yfmoc leef at stnaw ynopyreve ’nA
.ekil-yppah lla ’nilggaw
…ecafrus eht otni lil a tsuj knis yeht ’na
?og flesham tel hA
,edepmats wolley a syawla s’eH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.noitnetta a’retnec eht
.yfmoc ynop tseikcip eht neve ekam at neewteb ni ’niddap hguone htiw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.relluf neve eb d’raer ’na sknalf ’na tsehc ham dna
!seiP !srettirf tog eW
.dworc eht erofeb eip a dehsidnarb nrubearB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.’nissim er’yeht tahw me‘ wohs og os ,selppa sercA elppA teewS tog t’nia yeht tub
,tsrif ta esirprus lil a s’erehT
,emitemos niaga ti od ot evah d’hA em dlot ekaC .srM
.flesham dehsup hA ,nisuoC
,semit elpuoc a hctip selas ruo did ew retfA
,ria eht atni pu gum sih ’a dne eht deson hA
.ylleb ham ta dekool eH
airtseuqE a’ruot a ekam ot tuo tnes saw hA os dnA
.taht ees at desu reven hA
d’hA ’na ,dnim ,nosaes wols eht ’nirud tsuj—
.kaeps ot ’nivah uoy tuohtiw yas n’c ydob rey hcum woh ,’nizamA
.nrubearB ,nisuoc ham s’taht ’na
.’niklat t’nsaw eh ’na
.noitnetta ward s’ti ,syad eseht od n’c hA gnihtyna s’ereht fi ,lleW
seinop llet t’nac ay ,nisuoc ,lleW“
.niatruc gib a ’a tnorf ni elbat a ’nittup ’na
,wodniw eht ni ngis a dah skcans neve devres taht nwot ni ecalp yrevE
.dworc eht morf me‘ ees dluoc uoy os dnuor‘ nups slebal eht htiw
.esruoc ’a ,dworc a saw erehT
,nrubearB ot revo redic a’gum rehtona dils hA
!ynopyreve ,thgir s’tahT“
”!asoolelppaaaaA ot emocleW“
.hguone noos em otno dexaler tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,tsrif ta desirprus saw eH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.llams oot lil a tsuj s’nihtyreve taht ’nidnif nib hA ,tsenrae ni ’nitae detrats hA ecno tub ,allef gib a neeb syawla ev’hA
”!ylimaf elppA eht eb ll’ti
”?eip elppa ereh siht tnaw ahct’nod ,lleW“ ”.puyeE“
”.ereH staE caM giB“
.secaf rieht no skool eht ref tnuocca t’nod tahT
flesmih ’nittegreF .retsis sih ref koobloohcs nettogref a ffo ’nippord rehtorb gib lufitud a
.pu eson ham denrut ’na
.sisahpme ref em
,ssenisub ref dooG
.ni emac tsevrah elppa eht nehw ref sredro ekat ’na
.tnemssarrabme ni nwod tah sih gnillup
?nisuoc ,rettam eht s’tahW“
.seinop dexaler attol a ees hA
.ereh selppa tog yehT
”!maerc eci ’a poocs a htiw hsileeeed s’ti ’na ,ragus emos ,nomannic emoS
* * * ...?ereh tae hA ynopyreve llet at ekil ay d’woH
.noitnetta ref ’nimaercs dna ’nilbbow selppa neerg ’nimaelg ’na dehcterts owt htiw ,edih der thgirb ,yrebbulB
,ytpme eb d’ylleb ham—
yobdooG ydduB yb
,daeh sih no kcab ti ’nicalP
”?’niworG“ ”—llits si ssenziB
!won tiuq t’niac ooY
.ti fo hcni yna ffo wohs at diarfa eb annog t’nia I os
,doof lles at siht esu annog s’ynopyna fI“