.yad hcae ecracs erom erew hsif ehT
,thgirpu flesmih dehsup
,ot hsiw ton od ro dnatsrednu ton od ohw esoht yb
.deraeppa lluks raeb eht erofeb yad eht ylno tuo dnuof dah rehtaf s’uruiK
,tsehc eht nwod ekorts a
,yad taht no stirips on erew erehT
.tuo ti denword eci
.emit emas eht ta doog os tey dna
.elzzum sih morf gnippird loord dna gnilworg hcamots sih
,snoom ynam ni emit tsrif eht roF
,meht no thgiew tup ot deirt eh nehw yaw evag hcihw sehsub ro sdeer pota wons fo sdnuom hguorht gnihsup ,revir eht morf yawa ti wollof dluow eh
,eert hcrib dekoorc a htaeneb ,erehT .elcarim a
.morf gnihsif neeb d’eh eloh eht ssorca yltcerid
,enoemos tsniaga kcab gniyl saw eh desilaer uruiK .esolc yrev morf
,htaerb rehtona ward dluoc meht fo rehtie erofeB
,dnah ni dnah ,xof etihw dna
,flesti tserof yrev eht ,stirips ehT
,stirips eht yb dnA
?eh dluohs yhw ,lla retfA
.elzzum sih otni devohs eh taht hsif deird fo tuc ergaem a gnizies
.mih ta kcab gnirats ecaf eht morf rehtag dluoc uruiK lla saw tnemtnetnoC
,knab raf eht fo pot eht ot pu
.revir eht raen mih tpek ti dnA
.eloh eht yb espalloc ot htgnerts hguone tsuj dah eH
,tirips revir eht ot og llew sa thgim uoy“
,sehsub hguorht gnihsarc
.swaptoof desiurb sih
.reed eht no delbmuts tsrif d’eh thgin eht naht ,derit erom dna
”.gnihtemos tae ot eganam nac uoy fi ees ll’ew nehT
,ereht yal eh sa elzzum sih nwod demaerts sraeT
.yad a owt ro hcrep ynniks a hctac ot elba ylno saw eH
.emit siht ,dekan saw tI .gnihtemos
,ecargsid sih ees ot devil t’ndah ohw
.spahrep ,pmac siht nodnaba ot hguone nosaeR
,retaw eht dehcuot tsomla eson sih litnu flesmih derewol eH
,ihovatneL eht ekil sebirt fo ssenilnamnu emoshtaol eht fo selat dirul mih dlot tahT
.dias xof eht ”,etal oot uoy ot tog d’I thguoht I“ .smaerd sih nI
drawrof deppans gnirtswob eht
devohs neeb dah ecaf sih ekil dnim suoiriled sih gninrub seiromem ynam os ,sgnitaeb eht
.ssengnihton eiree na yb decalper saw sevael eht fo gniltsur eht neve dna stcesni fo zzub eht
ssensselemoh,sredrosid gnitae ,mrah-fles ,esuba gurd dna lohocla fo setar rehgih—
,wons dna dniw eht morf trofmoc llams a dedivorp ecno dah yeht erehW
,lla retfa ,ti denekaew evah thgim waht ehT
.swalc nwo sih fo yregavas eht ro
,pmac siht tfel dah srehsif nwonknu
,nihtiw nezorf hcrep llams ees dluoc eh kciht os saw tI
,hguohT .elpoep siH
,esruoc fO .nemo lli
.lufniap saw ti taht kcohs a fo hguone saw mih ekow taht htmraw ehT
,dnuos yldlrowrehto na saw tI
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
,mih ot esiw nettog yllanif
,noom lluf txen eht yb
:ekoj a fo sgninnigeb eht fo thguoht uruiK
,epaga gnignah wam dna rednow htiw ediw seye
,stnirptoof yb debrutsidnu demees mih dnuora tserof retniw eht
,gniraelc ytpme eht hguorht deohce sdrow siH
.knab peets eht nwod gnilbmut saw eh dna
,daeh sih koohs dna
yrevlis taht woh
mottob eht ot uoy nword ,uoy erul
,gniyas saw eh tahw sseug ot nigeb t’ndluoc uruiK
gnilriws dnim sih
,pu gnireep saw dna ,eci eht fo egde eht ta ,nwod tlenk dah eH
.gnireffus sih ni erusaelp koot yeht
.noitcelfer eht morf mih ta kcab gnilims xof revlis eht was flow etihw eht
,toof dna dnah yb
,flow eht demaercS ”,oN“
,thgilnus eht ni remmihs ot deraeppa taht revlis gnilzzad fo xim a saw ruf stI
,suoicilam erew stirips revir taht—
.taorht sih otni pael traeh sih tlef dna ,spil sti daer flow ehT
.kcen sti ni peed
.tes ot nageb nus eht taht hguone gnol saw ti tuB
,gnizalb seye ,derewol sreltna
.doolb dna hself nwo sih sa laer sa dekool ti uruiK ot dna
nael despalloc eht degnevacs dah ydobon taht debrutsid neeb evah dluohs eH .yltfos erom
,edis sih ni sevink ekil tlef dloc ehT
,eslaf era seititnedi ruo esuaceb ton neppah sgniht eseht lla
.eci eht ffo pu flesmih dekcip ylhsigguls uruiK
.reednier a doots
.ydaerla saw eh naht redloc yna eb ylbissop t’ndluoc
”?uoy ekil gnihtemos evol ot flesym esabed dluow I taht“
.tuo erugif ot drah ton saw tser eht dnA
,xof revlis eht fo ecaf eht no nees d’eh tahw tegrof t’ndluoc eh tuB
ni xof eht ,tirips revir eht fi tahw
.efil s’flow eht ni sgniht doog wef eht fo eno neeb dah amasuuK
.s’yrrauq sih ro nwo sih rehtie
.taerter citnarf a ni yawa gnigrahc
uruiK tub ,hcum t’nsaw tI
,hcni yb hcni tub
.taht evresed I ebyaM
.remraw saw tnet eht ni ria eht hguoht
,desserd ylerab erew uoY
!uoy KCIRT ot gniyrt s’tI
.tuo mih evord yllanif yeht nehw ebirt eht ni rehto yna naht reirgna
,floWcaM boR & xoFarakaS yb ”snoitcelfeR“ saw sihT     .kcab dekool
,esuorg fo elbrow eht ,tserof eht fo muh gnitrofmoc ecno ehT
,dnuos a draeh ylpmid eH
:ees lliw seye tsenoh tuB
,eniwt fo sparcs eht revocer ot kcab emoc ro
,daeh sih revo tpel reed eht nehw tuB
.rehtona eno htiw gniyal selam owt
.elpoep sih ot kcab og naht yawa rehtiw renoos dluow eh
,revir eht fo edis raf eht no sdnal ehT
uruiK nekatsim evah thgim yeht ,mih dnuof dah enoemos fI
,eci eht no gnidnats saw tI
.erac ot dloc oot dna ,yrgnuh oot
,gnisopmi won erew yeht
,dnuos eht fo ecruos eht sdrawot gninrut
,won ,reggib demees reed eht dnA
gnidnuop traeh sih
gnilkcarc fo raor a erofeb wolleb lufnruom a tuo gnittel
.fo kaeps ot tnecs on dah regnarts eht tub
,ecnaifed fo tca na htob si tressa ew seititnedi eht ni sepoh ruo lla ecalp oT
,spart gnikcehc elihw deraeppasid dah amasuuK
.mih evoba eci hsurb srae sih tlef eH .evah t’ndluoc eh
,niaga kcas sih htiw gnilbmuF
.semalf yrgnuh ekil derekcilf taht egnaro peed a dna
.pans giwt a draeh eh ,neht dnA
.evah ot ecnahc a nettog reven d’eh sessik eht ekil detsat ti taht denigami eh
,deffins eh sa gnihctiwt eson sih
,resolC .spets erom wef
dah tI .ecilam ekil dekool t’ndah tI
.retaw krad fo wam gnipag a yb elohw dewollaws saw erutaerc gnitadimitni eht ,tnatsni na nI
.tsaef a ekil tlef dah hsifnus a dednal eh yad eno ehT
,seye sih tem noitcelfer eht semitemoS
uoy esruC !uhrakiӒ uoy esruC
.ereh htaed dnif ylno
ylimaf remrof sih fo sedahs eht fo rethgual evisired eht ro
.denialpxe evah t’ndluoc uruiK syaw ni egnarts neeb dah
dennuts os saw uruiK
.mih htaeneb devaeh htrae elohw eht sa tlah a ot gniddiks dna wons eht otni stoob deggar sih gniggid
,dewollaws eh sA gnineddam saw tI
.flesmih dlot dah uruiK
.eurt era yeht esuaceb tub
flow eht sa noos sA
.htolcniol eht rednu wap a neve
thguat neeb syawla dah ebirt sih fo gnuoy eht lla—
.retaw eht otni dna ,egde
.nar dna denrut eh dna ,mih koot cinaP
enigami ot ton gniyrt
seussi eht fo rehtona ti ylpmi yehT
,revir eht morf knard eh nehW
.tserof eht fo sehctulc eht morf tsrub yllanif eh litnu
.niaga mraw er’uoy llit tsael ta
,uruiK sa devrats sa ylbaborp
ylevitnetta gnihctaw dna dexifsnart
,htaeneb doof neddih rof gnihcraes ,sevooh sti fo eno htiw wons eht ta gniwap saw tI
,dnatsrednu dluoc esle ydobon gnihtemos derahs yehT
,yks eht otni delwoh flow ehT ”!lla
!kcarc prahs a yb dewollof
.seenk sih ot llef eh dna
.niaga evom eht no ydaerla saw reednier eht tub
.tserof eht ni sgniht rehto ees ot nageb eh
.noitpo ylno eht netfo oot lla dna
.ecafrus s’retaw eht nekorb dah gnihtemos fi sa
.niaga xof eht saw
.taht rof efil sih ekat ot dediced dah stirips eht dna
,ti rebmemer ot evah d’eh ,ynnuf saw tahT
,ytinrete na ekil tlef tiaw ehT
.flesmih ta deppans uruiK ,loof uoy
.mih dnuora smra rieht
rehtar ro—xof ehT
.oot tnelis eb dluow yeht dehsiw eh
,worra sih fo tfah ehT
,won delttes dah eci ehT .gnivomnu
,pmac gnihsif denodnaba eht otni delbmuts d’eh woh rebmemer yleritne t’ndluoc eH
,seye sih gnisolC
.ecneserp s’retnuh eht ot suoivilbo llits
.psag ot deganam eh ”,uruiK m’I“ …llits tub ,esruoc fo
,hctiwt eson sti dehctaw eH .denword
.erohs ot kcab dereggats eh sa
:dnammoc eht fo noititeper eht spil sih no daer dluoc uruiK dna ,ekops—
.epoh sih fo tsal eht ti morf gnizeeuqs dna traeh sih dnuora flesti gnipparw ssenthgit a
,noziroh htuos eht fo egde eht gnola klaw ruoh eerht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
eno siht piks esaelp
.swalc prahs sih htiw ruf sih otni gniggid dna lluks sih gnihctulc
.netsil ot srae gnilliw on gnidnif
.eloh eht ot flesmih deggard eh
,daeh sih detfil flow ehT
.esolc saw eci eht ni eloh eht tub
,rewol dna rewol knas uruiK
,oN .mih nekasrof dah
.eci eht ssorca flesmih deggard uruiK
.sdoow eht ni repeed morf ,ylgnikcom
,yawa og ot meht
.tnet nikslaes tink-ylthgit a fo foor eht ees dluoc flow eht mih evobA
.wons eht ni mih htaenrednu erehwemos yal dna
,enola lliw fo ecrof yb
,eurt ekops srepsihw ’snomed ehT
.anuas eht ni selam redlo eht fo seenk eht neewteb secnalg gnilaets ro
,noitavrats morf tnuag
.elpoep reh naht citehtapmys erom yna eb dluow
,gnihton naht retteb saw tI
thguat neeb syawla d’eH
,deliocer reednier ehT
tneps d’eh emit eht lla roF
.rehtaf sih ekil dednuos daeh sih ni eciov ehT
.gninefaed saw nosaeS htraeH eht deinapmocca taht ecnelis ehT  floWcaM boR & xoFarakaS yb ”snoitcelfeR“
,deunitnoc laapiluT ”,emahs a neeb evah dluow tI“
:nwo ruo ni ees ew seitilibissop eht ni
,retsasid fo ekops ereh ecneserp rieht yleruS
,htmraw s’xof eht tsniaga sdrawkcab elgguns ot eros oot llits erew sbmil siH
,evom ot elzzum sih decrof uruiK tub ,klat ot tluciffid saw ti ”…s’tI“
,delf dah eh erofeb stoob niks revaeb fo riap a debbarg evah ot ykcul flesmih detnuoc uruiK
.troffe eht htiw gninnips daeh sih
.mih htaeneb eci
.rethgual delaecnoc htiw deworran seyE
.tuo dnif reven dluow eh tuB
.etihw nialp ylno
.evoba yks yerg eht sdrawot ecaf sih denrut dna tnemom a rof deppots uruiK
,retaw eht hcuot ot nwod wap a dehcaer eh sA
.reven ro won saw tI
.stirips dekciw tuoba rednow ot nugeb d’eh dnA
,tsim fo ffup a ni elzzum sih depacse esruc rehtonA
.erom ecno enola tfel saw uruiK dna
,ria sih fo tsal ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.revo koot tcnitsni dna detaerter dnim sih ni snomed eht ,tnatsni na nI
.neeb evah t’ndluoc ti ,oN
.sloot yratnemidur sih fo hcaer eht dnoyeb
,yawa rednaw ylmlac ot emit dah reed eht taht
,pu denepo tserof eht ylnedduS
.etipser elttil dereffo sgniggel dna cinut rehtael deggar eht sa yltneloiv gnirevihs ydob elohw sih
.gnibrutsid dnif yam srenetsil emos rettam tcejbus sniatnoc yrots s’yadoT
,stlusni eht ,gnituohs ehT
.reed emas eht saw ti tbuod t’ndluoc uruiK dnA
.deciton ylerab eh taht revir eht ni xof eht gnihctaw ysub os saw uruiK
,noitcelfer eht eciton t’ndid eH .esahc evig ot dna
.seot sih ni ssenbmun eht fo sseldeeh
a drawrof dehcni dna daeh sti dewob yerp sih litnu
,sgel dnih sti otno pu deraer reednier ehT
.erom ecno mih tsniaga nrut dluow etaf fo sdniw ehT
”.devrats tsomla kool uoy rednow on s’ti ,srotsecna eht yB
,ruf eht ni revlis gniremmihs on saw erehT
.edis ot edis morf gniggaw neve liat sih
,nruter ot nageb llems fo esnes sih sa dnA .nwo sih sa
,won tserof ytpme na ylno saw erehT
,ylduol dewehc eh sa ydluom detsat tI
,gnipoord sdileye sih
,erehwemos tsewhtuos eht ot
.hcaer fo tuo ylerab tsuj syawla ,egnaro-rebme dna
.kle eht nekat dah taht sretaw eht fo noitcelfer eht ni
,gnimusnoc-lla erew seye eulb krad esoht
ytiniffA ruF no erom dnif nac uoy dna
.eci eht ni eloh eht yb dessap eh sa gnihgual
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF ehT yb gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW ygolohtna gninniw-drawa eht ni meht fo htob morf seirots dnif nac uoY .pleh ot yppah s’ohw ,floWcaM boR & ,siht hsinif pleh ot emit sih gnireffo boR detaicerppa yllaer ohw
revir ehT …nehW
.hcnelc selcsum sih edam taht
,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer
,ekatsim sih desilaer eh etal ooT
.retaw krad eht otni dna eci eht fo egde eht revo gniliart eniwt fo htgnel niht
.snopaew ro sloot on
.gnirtswob eht htiw pu worra eht enil ot gnilggurts sregnif bmun sih ,worra eht htiw delbmuf eh sa elzzum s’flow eht dellif sesruc derepsihW .ecnahc dnoces a evah t’ndluow eH
,yrawnu eht kcirt ot tuo syawla ,yrgnuh
,sdoow eht ni ecalp laiceps rieht ni syad sseltnuoc tneps dah yeht dnA
,deliaf gnivah esle lla htiW
maerts eht denil taht seert eht fo retlehs eht tfel dah tI
,ynitsed nwo sih ekam ot ebirt sih delf dah eH
,lufyalp tsomla ,detlit daeH
”!em ot siht od t’nac uoy“ ,worros htiw dellif dna esraoh eciov sih
?xof sih saw erehW
…nehw xof derruf-revlis eht ot ti llet ot
.gniog peek ot evah dluow eh
s’uruiK ,wons eht ni ereht gnidnatS
,dessessop ydob detaicame sih htgnerts elttil tahw htiW
.tuo flow eht gard ot
.enog dah uruiK erehw gnirednow fi sa ,dekrep srae
,knab eht no kcab
xof eht taht dna
.mih tsap gnihsur seert fo serugif ywodahs eht
ekops eh nehw semitemoS .em dniF
,laapiluT m’I“ .evila mih dnuof evah ot yppah yrev eb ot demees yal eh smra esohw ni
.won meht ezingocer t’ndid uruiK neht nwonk d’eh eman esohw enoyna saw ti fi
.etulosba dna gnibmun saw retaw eht fo dloc ehT
eht revo flesmih dellup eh neht dnA
.uruiK part dna ni esolc ot gnimees sbmil rieht
.secarbme on ,swap tfos oN
.tserof krad eht hguorht detnirps eh sa laref tsomla ecaf sih no kool eht
,wap tnecsediri sti ni enil sih fo dne rehto eht
.maerts nezorf a gnola delffuhs ohw flow etihw enol a tpecxe lla ,neve daed
,gniteelf nus retniw eht ,ylneddus emac thgiN
.ti rof demalb saw uruiK dna
.nrocs rieht fo seohce eht htiw niaga enola saw uruiK neht dna ,dezingocer dna nees eb ot hguone gnol ereht ylno erew meht fo
,mih del reed eht hcihw hguorht
,flesti dnefed naht rehtar tuB
…niaga meht denepo eh nehw tuB
.niap on leef ot demees ti won hguoht
,daeh sih detfil uruiK
,kcab nward erew spil s’rehtaf sih ”,tluaf ruoy s’tI“
,reednier daed a htiw sretaw sti detullop dna rebmuls peed a morf ti desuor dah eh taht yrgna
,yad htruof eht nO
na ti deralced dna sdoow eht ni lluks s’raeb a dnuof ecno dah namahs s’ebirt sih woh ekil
,meht mraw erif eht pleh oT .desilaer uruiK ,dehtolc saw meht fo rehtien dnA
,flesmih dnif ot ylno
,detsisni laapiluT ,etam sih
pota nihc sih dial dna
,gnihctaw saw uruiK erus saw eh nehw
,deksa neeb netfo sah tI
,wons eht ni seenk sih ot knas uruiK
,retaw eht otni ,ebyam pu ro
.ecaf sih tsniaga slaoc evil ekil
.flow eht ta derats won ti erehw ot knab raf eht morf del wons eht ni skcart oN
,reednier eht ot ecnatsid eht gnisolc yldipar saw flow etihw ehT
eht deppat wob fo esab eht litnu
nem htiw yal dluow nem dias saw ti erehw
.seot sih ni seldeen ekil tlef tI
,shtped eht otni kcab dedaf ecaf s’regnarts eht
.yaw evag reednier eht htaeneb eci eht sa dehctaw uruiK
,tsehc dna ,ecaf s’flow eht desserac wap siH
denepeed thgin eht sa tuB
,edis sti otno nworht saw reednier eht taht evom ti did yltneloiv oS
,mih sdrawot evom ot nugeb dna
?mih rof tsuj ngis a neeb ti daH
revlis-elacshsif ruf
.etib a neve ton saw ereht yad driht eht nO
,erif gnigar a fo mih dlot ti
,xof a sa ti deyarteb srae prahs dna elzzum keels ehT
mih dehsuhs xof eht ”,hhhhS“ ”…uoy s’tI“
.knurt derevoc-wons a rednu wolloh a morf ,niatfeihc eht detuohs ”!hcel luoF“
,ngis on saw ereht reed eht fO
,siht ta ezorf uruiK
.dloc dna noitavrats fo syad eerht rof
,ti gniusrup neeb d’eh gnol woh fo kcart tsol uruiK
,ria ytpme dna wons tub gnihton no dednal toof sih ylneddus nehT
.revir eht ron reed eht rehtien dnif dluoc eH
,worra na ro efink a rof dnuora tlef uruiK
,wodaem a saw ti thguoht eh ,tsael tA
gnillaf wons eht dna rettib
,seloptnet eht no yrd ot gnignah ,sehtolc eht fo emos dezingocer eH
,noitcelfer yretaw eht ni xof eht htiw dellif erew smaerd sih dna ,yrgnuh tpels eH
.dias xof eht ”,yaw eht yb
,ffo raf morf fi sa
,retaw eht otni dehcaer eh fi hguoht sa tlef flow eht tey dnA
,wons eht hguorht yldrawkwa dehcnurc sevooh stI
dah eh ,tsap noom eht fo gninrut eno ylno ,thgin lufetaf taht nO
,tsehc sih ni gnizies traeh sih
,dehcaorppa ti sA
.drawrof deps worra eht dna
.ydob nwo sih fo thgiew eht rednu gnitnurg
,dehca ydob sih fo trap yrevE
ssenneddus a htiw mih fo trap yreve dehcaer tI
,taht htiW …em dniF
,raeb motnahp taerg a fo nway eht ekil
,dlihc a deirc ”!trevreP“
.lortnoc ton dluoc flow eht gnihtemos rof mih gnikcom erew stirips eht hguoht sa tlef tI
,deklaw eh sa dewob saw daeh s’uruiK
ruo no hcum os tsisni ew yhw
,wonk did uruiK tahw fo dnA .syaw
kaos retaw yci tel dna tilps dah meht no smaes eht neve tub
.eromyna dloc eht leef neve t’ndluoc eH .ruf revlis oN
.ekal eht fo edis raf eht no revir a tuo dekcip eh noisiv yrrulb hguorhT
.denettalf srae s’uruiK
.meht fo flesmih eerf ot yaw eno ylno was uruiK
,redluohs sih morf gnuh taht kcas llams a otni wap a devohs eh ,yletarepseD
.revir eht ot kcab neht
.wam gnimusnoc-lla eht fo egde eht rof depael uruiK
,mih ta gnizag saw reed eht ,emit hcaE
,stirips dekciw fo ecneserp eht ro
,emoclew ekil dekool
dah ro ,gninword erew yeht taht ngis on ,cinap ro raef oN
egnarts rieht dna stirips eht fo smihw eht ta ylerem saw eh taht tuohtiw dna ,evila ro daed
,nwod saw ti ecnO
,raeps tfihsekam sih pirg ot derebmemer flow eht erofeb mih ta kcab kool neht dna
,uoy rof gnittespu eb yam mrah-fles ot detaler seslupmi dna sthguoht fo noitpircsed fI
,stnih eltbus fo mrof eht ni emac syawla sngis taht saw ti
,tiripS reviR lufegnev a fo kcirt emos saw siht fI
.sehcni erem yb elzzum sih dessim sevooh raer prahs sti fo enO
,eci eht otno depael dna
,ti thguac eh nehw od dluow eh tahw erus neve t’nsaw flow ehT
,htgnerts sih fo tsal eht
revetahw morf degnevacs
,dnim sih ni erehwemoS
erom hcum ylniatrec ,regnorts
,drawno dehcram eh oS
,stoor wolliw eht rednu ot-
s’uruiK .noitcafsitas yna reven
,etoyoC triD yb daeR  .yrruFoS ro
amasuuK ta gnol oot gnikool mih thguac d’eh nehw mih ta delrans taht eciov emas ehT
?flesruoy yb ereh tuo yaw eht lla pu dniw uoy did htrae no woH“
,enoemos dias
,eno llams a ylno saw tI
,swap esoht yb dehcuot eb ot leef dluow ti woh derednow
,won tser tsuJ“ .daeh s’uruiK
.eci eht no kcab flesmih dnuof dna
.detniop dna dekeirhs retsis sih ”!larutannU“
.tsaeb emas eht saw ti nwonk evah t’ndluow
”,kniht yllaer uoy diD“
,mih htaeneb tuo evag sgel gnilbmert s’flow eht ,ylwolS
od naht erom reffus ew yllacitsitats taht—
.noitcelfer s’xof eht ekil ,kcab delims eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yad taht hsif on thguac uruiK
-neve ebyam dna ,noitingocer dna
.oot mih wollaws ot ti deggeb llits eh tey
,espalloc ot ydaer saw ti ekil dekool reednier gnipmil eht sa tsuJ
:sevlesmeht eb ot demees t’ndah snoitceriD
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.tnatsid sedirts wef a ylno gnileenk flow etihw eht fo erawanu
.mih drawot hsurb eht hguorht gnihsarc gnihtemos eciton t’ndid tsomla eH
.wons eht otni deraeppasid dah ti tub
.snoitcelfer eht lla ni wonk ot emoc d’eh ecaf eht saw siht tbuod on saw ereht tuB
ti fo tuo deliart eniwt gnihsif fo htgnel siH
.seititnedi hcus ees ot hsiw ton seod taht yteicos a yb ,su ot enod sgniht era esehT
,ti kconk ot elba yllanif saw eh litnu
.noisulli fo yretsam a hcuS
.thgirpu depmuj uruiK
.taht wenk enoyrevE
,gnisaet dnoyeb gnihton
.mih dnuora retaw kcalb tub gnihton ees dluoc eH
etarelot dluow ebirt eht rehtehw deksa dah flow eht nehw desufnoc dna delffab neeb dah—
fi sdoow eht otni yawa nemow evird dna
lliw uoY .meht ot kcab og ,pu eviG
,htworgrednu eht hguorht reed eht fo gnihsarc eht saw tserof eht fo tuo mih desahc taht dnuos eht fi llet ton dluoc eH
.kcab saw reednier eht
?kooh eht no saw tahw saw eh dna
.elbissopmi dnoyeb ,elbissopmi saw tI
.tsif dellab a htiw eci eht kcurts eh sa sraet htiw pu gnillew seye
.sdoow eht otni raeppasid skcart nwo sih was eh erehw morf sedirts wef a ylnO
.eb dluow ti dloc woh
.sseug t’ndluoc flow eht
.etamitigelli eb ot seititnedi esoht sevorp wohemos siht fi sA .elpoep thgiarts
.sih tem taht seye eht fo eulb eht ot shtped yks-thgin ylhtraenu oN
drow taht kniht ot flesmih hcaet ot drah gnikrow llits saw uruiK hguoht
gnilbmuts flow eht
,oot revir eht otni enog evah tsum eh ,esruoc fO
,doolb sih derahs ohw snamahs on fo wenk flow ehT
.dnatsrednu ton dluoc yeht tahw yortsed ot denimreted elpoep ylno
,redrah detnap eH
.ylluferac eci eht dessorc yehT
.ti erongi ot dah tsuj eh
.taebtraeh gnidnuop hcae htiw niatrec erom emaceb ylno mood stI
.flesmih hcuot ot nigeb dna ,elims dluow
,sehcnarb gnitacoffus eht edisa dehsams eh
,raeps sih rof delbmuf uruiK
.krow ti ekam ot dah
,gniyarts ro gninrut tuohtiw
,deppans hctelf eht
.derebmemer eh naht regral dekool tI
.pu dekool flow ehT
,tuo dleh smra sih htiW
,ees ot hguone thgil saw ti sa noos sa ,emit yrevE
.rehtegot ,ebirt rieht fo htarw eht epacse ot
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
.detatiseh tub ,stirips eht ot sknaht reffo ot htuom sih denepo eH
.mih devresed yeht neht
,thgin hcae erom dna erom ,smaerd
dah ti thguoht flow eht emit hcaE
,resolc ni denael iruiK
.skooh enob eht ro
.kcen sih fo ffurcs eht yb mih barg gnihtemos tlef eh
,ti no gniremmis htorb fo
enots toh ekil tlef ydob siH
.ot tnaw yeht did ron
.edis eht ot delbmarcs eh
,detsugsid ,dereens amasuuK
,ecilam ekil dekool t’ndah ti ESRUOC fO
stpmetta elpitlum koot tI
rieht rof esor nus eht semit eerht txen ehT
dna sknabwons hguorht gnirednulb
.selffins dna sbos fo paeh a otni despalloc eh dna dekcarc yllanif eciov sih erofeb
worra na fo ycrem eht yb rehtehw ,tuo gnihtemos erugif dluow eh tub
!stiripS reviR uoy esruC“
.flow eht morf yawa shtgnel-mra eerht naht erom on saw reednier eht litnu ,resolc
,tiperif eht morf yltcerid nekat
”?!hguone hguorht neeb I t’nevaH
.mih ta kcab gnirats saw regnarts A
.llems dna leef dluow ruf
.elzzum sti ssorca kcil eugnot sti ,knilb seye sti
.ebirt sih ot kcab yenruoj eht rof eraperp dna ,tnet eht nwod ekat laapiluT depleh uriuK dnA .od ,yllautneve sretniw dna ,spans dloc sa ,dedne pans dloc eht hguone nooS
.doof saw doof tub
tuoba deleehw ylneddus reednier eht
.nees tsuj dah eh tahw fo esnes ekam ot deirt eh sa
,reirgnuh dna ,redloc saw eH
ssel dniw eht dnif ot pu nekow d’eh tub
kcuts worra na
”.ni llaf uoy ees ot emit ni tsuj pu dekool ylno I“
erus tlef uruiK eh rehtar ro—ti semitemoS
flow etihw a fo noitcelfer eht ylnO .ylluferac
dna reduol deraor dah tahT
.gnorw yrev saw gnihtemos mih dlot gnileef tug a litnu
,nar eh sa dnilb tsomla saw flow ehT  .ebirt dna
uruiK kcen sti ni worra sih rof neeb t’ndah ti fI .evissergga
.ecaf sih derevoc flow eht sa sdrawkcab gnillaf
”?yeht t’ndluow yhW“
,yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
?mih detnaw dah taht tirips revir eht saw erehW
si yrots s’yadoT
morf yawa mih del dah ti semit ynam woh fo dna
.yks thgin raelc a fo esnapxe
.stirips leurc rof yot a pu dniw ot ylno
,laem toh a rof nraey mih edam meht fo thgis erem ehT
.nosaes siht ni ton tsael ta
.hguone dah yllanif
.enil eht no hsif on tlef eh tub
,gniveileb yb enod eb tsum ti fi nevE
uruiK tnes taht yrc gniyfirret a tuo gnittel
”.si ti sa luof sa tib yreve er’uoy fi
egami eht morf deraeppasid yeht nehw tnew swap esoht erehw dna
,ni dekool dna eloh eht yb deppots yeht ,ecnetsisni
.tsol saw eh desilaer uruiK
sa debircsed eb ylno dluoc tahw dnuof eh erehw
,xoFarakaS yb ”snoitcelfeR“
s’uruiK tA .mrif dleh ti tub
!namahs on sah ebirt eht taht“ ,derab hteet
.esrow raf saw hturt eht tuB
.thgilnoom eht ni enohs ylraen xof eht fo noitcelfer ehT
,ti tohs d’eh erehw yltcaxe kcen sti fo edis eht ni deirub llits saw
.won dah eh ynapmoc ylno eht erew sthguoht siH
,retaw kcalb ykni eht otni derats eH
eht ta derats uruiK
,tsenoh erew flow eht fi dnA
.sdapwap sih tsniaga gnihsurb ruf tfos leef dluow eh
.eci eht ni eloh eht revo gnihcuorc ydaerla uruiK dnuof yeht
.gnol tsal t’ndluow ti tuB
,emit a rof detiaw eh
,ytleurc rieht fo etips ni nevE
,yas yeht ,yleruS ’.ytitnedi‘
.dlrow eht ni devil taht lla derehtoms dah llafwons sseldne eht ekiL
,enil gnihsif eht ni gnillup eno eht saw
.elims a otni lruc elzzum sih tlef uruiK
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY  .emit rehtona
.resolc elttil a tsuJ
.hcus sa mih detaert reven yeht
,uhrakiӒ ,rehtoM raeB ehT kniht ot evian saw eh spahreP
,eci eht fo egde eht revo gnignah llits
,meht no dellevart ro delttes netfo sebirt dna tsav erew sreviR
,tsehc rieht tsniaga daeh sih
.yhtlaeh eb tonnac siht
,retaw eht ot resolc flesmih deggard flow eht ,ylwolS
,miws ot htgnerts eht dah llits d’eh fi nevE
mih detpurroc t’ndah uoy fi mih nekat evah reven dluow stirips ehT
,noitcelfer eht
…krad tnew gnihtyreve ,nehT
,dah eh htgnerts elttil eht htiw gnihsup
.mih fo daeha eci eht no dexif seye
.stiripS reviR yrgna fo taerht eht etipsed
.naorg stoob sih htaeneb dnuorg yrev eht draeh uruiK
.raeb deiznerf a ekil ti retfa gnitnirps dna
,syaw larutannu s’flow eht fo mitciv a saw retnuh roop eht dias yehT
,debbos dna swap sih otni ecaf sih desserp eH
?mih erutrot stirips eht gnittel no og yhW
?em erutrot uoy od yhW“
.htuom sti denepo noitcelfer eht
.tsim enif a sa esir htaerb sih dehctaw eh sa rednaw ot nageb dnim
,keehc eht no sserac A
sseldnuob eht ekil
meht hcaE ”!ssenlufnamnu yhtlif ruoy htiw
…erahs emoc ot mih gnitivni fi sa
,tsrif ta evom t’ndid eH
dekcub reednier eht
,seye etarepsed hguorhT
.laapiluT ot gnidrocca ,oot s’uruiK
,mih koot ssensuoicsnocnu erofeb tsuJ
sih ni hctiwt enil eht tlef eH
deggeb ,htaerb sih rednu ylbeef derettum eH
revo deldduh neeb d’eh eci eht ni eloh eht ta nwod gnikool
.mih ta pu delims retaw eht ni xof ehT
?gnignis spahrep ro
.erif gniraor a otni
,lortnoc rieht fo eerf
,rettam t’ndid tI
,rehtomdnarg sih dias ”,neht oG“
”!lla retfa evila er’uoY“
,nwod dekool neve eh erofeb dellup eH .swap
.htuom sih fo tuo delbbub ,htmraw sih dna
,gnidnuop traeh ,gnivaeh tsehc
.smra dloc ,dloc rieht ni reverof ereht tsohg ruoy peek dna
,eil a fo kniht ot deen dluow eH
,doog ton saw gnihsif ehT
saw ecaf siH .motnahp a rof
redluohs sih revo wob sih gnissot ,esahc evag flow ehT
.kcas sih morf worra tnulb a koot dna sredluohs sih dnuora morf wob tfihsekam sih deppils eH
.nwo s’uruiK ekil gnilbmert sgel gnol
,retaw krad eht ni detcelfer ,daetsnI
.murd lautir a ekil
,derit oot saw flow etihw eht tuB .htob ro
tesnus eht htiw der dekaerts saw yks eht sa dna
,mih htaeneb tfihs ot deunitnoc eci eht sa nevE
.tpmetta eht deciton d’eh dias tuons s’laapiluT no elims eht tub
,taht naht erom gnihtoN
.tohs sih mia ot flow eht rof hguone gnol tsuj rof wons eht ni gnilbmuts
,noitisop gnihcuorc a otni flesmih detfil eh sa rethgirb wolg ot demees seye s’flow ehT
.mih ta gnilimS .saw ti xof fI
.wons kciht ni derevoc wodaem nepo ediw a ssorca gnitnirps flesmih dnuof uruiK dna
.srotaderp rof kcehc ot gnileviws srae sti ,spets wef yreve gnitatiseh reednier eht
.rekciht werg ekaw sti ni tfel ti liart nosmirc eht sa gniliaf ydob nwo sti
.rethguad a ot htrib evig derad yeht
.ssyba krad eht revo yleerf gnah tsehc sih gnittel
”.uoy sa emosdnah sa flow a ekat tirips revir eht tel ot“
.sdrow tnelis owt ekops ti sa
,nwod teef sih delgnad dna eci eht fo egde eht no tas noitcelfer eht semitemoS
-saw eh tahw tuo dnuof xof siht fi
.od dluow enotsremmah hguone yvaeh a neve ro
.mih devrats reven dah ebirt sih
.srae sih neewteb delzzun eson sih
koot ti fi sa tlef noitom yrevE