.mih ta pu delims I ”.uoy ni eveileb llits ll’I ,selcatsbo dna segnellahc eht etipseD“
”.wonk enoyna tel t’ndluoc I
”.thgin lla seipocotohp edam tsuj I
eud tsewhtroN cificaP eht ni seno roodni erew sloop cilbup lla
.ylgnignol tsomla ,dias eh ”,haeY“
,tekcaj mined a dna sgniggel ni lesaew a htiw deyalp esuolb dna nagidrac dezisrevo na ni xnyl a selbat loop eht fo eno tA .ytpme ylevitaler llits saw ti tub
”.knird eno eht tsuj htiw doog m’I ,oN“
.roolf eht fo daetsni emit eht lla sriahc ni gnittis ot desu saw I ecnis ,retaw wollahs eht ni deggel ssorc gnittis hguot saw tI
”.od ot tahw wonk t’nod I
.drah s’tI“
.gnizigolopa peek ot deen t’nod uoy dna“
.segaugnal gnihctiws dias dad ym ”,hsilgnE ni kaeps nac eW“
.ylgnikoj deksa eh ”?thgir ,ecalp emas eht ta evil llits stnerap ruoY“
.gniht emiteno a tsuj t’nsi tuo gnimoc naem I“
”.uoy hcaet nac ew sseug I neht …nrael ot tnaw yllaer uoy fi ,yakO“
,revaeb evitcetorprevo tey
”?thgir ,wNPU ta raey driht ruoy s’tI
,elpmet dnetta ot elttaeS ot evird eht ekam dluow ylimaf ym
”.egaw muminim evoba ekam neve t’nac I tub
.liomrut fo emit a ni rehto hcae dnuof lrig ytic a dna yob yrtnuoc a woh tuoba sekoj edam syawla meht fo owt ehT
.yrros yas ot deen t’nod yllaer uoY .thgirla s’tI“
,deksa dna kcen sih fo kcab eht debbur eh tnemom a retfA
”.uoy dnatsrednu llits nac I tsael ta
a otni gninrut saw yks eht sa nus gnittes eht ni renroc eht dednuor kcurt pukcip nooram s’droF
.deksa mom ym ”?ti ekil uoy oD“
”.sraey eerht tsomlA“
”,tnereffid adnik llits s’ti em rof tub ,efil ruoy gnitsaw tuoba leef uoy woh dnatsrednu nac I“
dna tae nac uoY
.deracs saw I dna ,ot ton flesym dlot tsuj I dekil I taht syug was I nehW
.ti detekcop I dna ,tekcit eht em dils ,sag eht rof pu em gnar eH
.ezag ym gnitreva dias I ”,erom uoy gnigassem ton rof yrros ma yllaer I dna ,sknahT“
.mih ta denworf I dna ,dias dad ym ”,ecir ekam ot woh wonk neve t’nod uoy ,no emoc ,eilrahC .thgirlA“
.eciov reh ni nrecnoc emos htiw dias ehs ”,eilrahC ,thgirla s’tI“
,dias eh ”,og uoy erofeB“
”.em egduj t’now ylbaborp uoy wonk I dna
.dednopser I ”,dael eht ekaT“
.flesruoy no naht
.ti rof pu ekam ot potpal llams a em thguob osla yehT
.denworf I ”.ykcus s’tahT“
,detcepxe reve ev’dluoc I naht evititepmoc dna detacilpmoc erom s’dlrow taht denrael I ,lleW“
”.snosaer ruoy dah uoy erus m’I neht wonk did uoy fi dna
”.kool taht em gnivig er’uoY“
.lohocla deniatnoc ti fi sa detcaer dna ,ados sih fo pis rehtona koot na dias eh ”,cisum dna swohs ni etsat ruo tsuj ton s’ti tuB“
…ti revo m’I .thgirla s’tI“
,stsoc yarfed pleh dluow ti dna ,gnola nettog syawla ev’eW !dneirf ym er’uoY !esruoc fO“
,pu gnimoc saw raeY weN oaL
,efil ym htiw od ot tnaw I tahw wonk t’nod llits I
.elims gnirussaer a em gnivig ,dias dad ym ”,rennid uoy edam eW“
.elbissop sa hcum sa troppus ym wohs ot gniyrt
,moderob dna trofmocsid fo yenruoj gnol a tsuj saw notgnihsaW lartnec ot gnivird dna ,kaerb gnirps gnirud tnemtrapa ym ta deyats tsuj ev’dluohs I ebyam gnikniht saw em fo trap A
.meht htiw emit dneps dluohs I wenk I os ,sraey ni em nees t’ndah yeht dna ylenol leef ot tnaw t’ndid I neht tub
.sessalg rieht morf knird a koot htob yeht dna dereehc owt ehT .tohs a knus ohw
,emit trohs a rof dnuora ylno ,spahrep ,dneirf dlo nA
.deksa I ”?esle enoyna dlot uoy evah ,loohcs hgih ni yag gnieb fo gnikaepS“
”.dnuora em htiw hsilgnE kaeps ot deen t’nod yllaer uoY“
.dil eht no gnitirw oaL htiw raj a morf redwop etihw emos dna ,eciuj emil ,secips ,secuas ,ragus ,retaw rehtegot xim mom ym dna seiggev emos pu ecid dad ym dehctaw I
,tnemtraped gnitnuocca eht ni ynapmoc emas eht ta gnikrow detrats yeht yltnecer dias yehT
”,yeksihW llaweriF morf edam denoihsaf dlo na s’tahT“
.yrf a otni tib ylwols neht eH
”.rehtegot yalp nac ew won ,looC“
,erom retnec QTBGL eht ot gniog eb dluohs I wonk I
”?uoy fo owt eht rof detrats teg I nac tahW“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.taht dnatsrednu nac I“
.elims yrw a em evag eh dna ,redluohs sih no wap ym tup I
.ecamirg a htiw dias eh ”,renoos uoy ot tuo gnimoc ton rof yrros m’I“
.sedacsaC eht otni gnidaeh noitavele eht ot tsujda ot deirt yeht sa pop ot srae ym rof elihw a koot tI
”,rekrow-drah a llits er’uoy wonk ot doog s’ti tub ,taht raeh ot yrros m’I“
taht flesym dlot I yaw siht gnileef morf flesym pots t’ndluoc I dezilaer I retfA
.retrauq a em dednah dna dias tar llat eht ”,srenniw er’ew fi ees s’teL“ ”.sknird
”.rehtegot kaerb remmus tsal ruo saw nosrep ni uoy was I emit tsaL“
.rojam ym ni tsactuo na em edam taht wohemos tub ,elpoep truh taht metsys a otni deef ro hcir emoceb ot tnaw t’ndid I
.mih ot kcab dias I ”,emit ruoy pu ekat ot naem t’ndid I ,yrroS“
.dias I ”,eb nac tI“
.enohp sih morf segassem txet eht
.nos ,lla ta melborp on
,loohcs elddim ni erew ew nehw em ot dnik os syawla erew uoY
.seirarbil dna smuesum lacirotsih naciremA naisA etaerc dna htuoy reeuq rof sretlehs sselemoh ekil sgniht trats ot detnaw I
.eno driht eht no elbbird ebuc eci na
.noitseuq eht ta deretlaf sreksihw sih dna deksa tar eht ”?mih gnitad uoY“
.reisae era sessalc ym ecnis ,otni teg nac I pihsnretni yreve gnikrow neeb tsuj ev’I egelloc ni m’I taht woN
.nirg gib a em tohs eh
”.gnizama si siht ,oN“
.W.N.P.U saw noitaiverbba eht ecnis
”.raey ruo detaudarg taht elpoep fo tol a htiw yaw taht smees tsuj ti sseug I
”.eruliaf rof pu em gnittes fo mih desucca I neht dna
”?ot pu neeb uoy evah tahw ,os ...eurt s’tahT“
.niaga deddon I
.taes regnessap eht ni enieffac fo esac kcap-ruof a dah I ,yllufknahT
,diulf der eht fo emos dellips I dna rac eht delttar pmub A
,draob trad cinortcele eht ta snrut koot regdab dna knuks A
.yltneg dias I ”,ezigolopa ot evah t’nod uoy ,niagA“
.reeb toor sih fo pis nellus a koot eH
.sksed gnitaolf no enod krowemoh gnitteg ro gnidaer elihw edaw dluoc stneduts erehw ,loop wollahs ,egral a saw hcihw
.noitces eeffoc delttob eht fo flehs pot eht morf gnihtemos hcaer flow eht pleh mih dehctaw I sa knat ym pu dellif I
.dereffo mom ym ”,uoy ot ti nialpxe nac ew tub
,kool nrets a em evag dad yM
”.rennid eta ydaerla I“
moor yduts retaw a dah yrarbil ygolonhceT dna ecneicS s’wNPU fo tnemesab ehT
”.ereh fo tuo teg ot deen yllaer I“
”.meht llac neve ylerab I dna ,meht morf ecnawolla na tuohtiw yb teg nac I yad eno yllufepoH“
.elims a mih evag I
.yawevird eht ot em deklaw dna yadhtrib htneetxis ym no em dedlofdnilb stnerap ym nehw emit eht derutcip osla I
.dloc dna niar eht lla ot
.sbir ym dehsurc eh sa kcab mih guh ot gniyrt dias I ”,doog ’nioD“
.ti denrael yeht woh s’ti os ,soaL ni senizagam dna srepapswen eht ni dna VT no saw tahw saw taht dias stnerap ym tub ,iahT wonk t’ndid I
.stnemertuocca ym ot gnitniop dias I ”,hctam ot su detnaw tsuj I“
.seirecorg gnitteg saw tuoba gniklat erew yeht lla nehw
…ysaeuq llits tub retteb tol a leef I
.loohcs ssenisub eht ni stneduts darg eht htiw krowten ot gniyrt setamssalc emos htiw hcnurb ot tnew I ecnis ,tius ssenisub a gniraew llits saw I
”.taef redrah a eb ot gniog si srehto htiw tsenoh siht gnieb gnileef a evah I“
,dias dna deddon I
.rehtegot eciffo eht ni gnieb fo snoitalubirt dna slairt eht lla em dlot yeht os
ta dezitonpyh saw rab eht ta xof rekib a elihw
.ni deppets I sa tuons ym dekcilf doof deirf dna ezoob fo llems ehT
.laicremmoc eivom a was I moor gnivil eht dnuora spal wef a retfA
.erauqs tekcop gnihctam dna eit dialp a htiw tius deewt a ni
wobniar detarutas dna thgirb a ni degnarra srethgil fo yalpsid a ot txen stols evitcepser rieht htaenrednu stekcit ffo hctarcs gnicalp dnuora denrut saw tar nworb ,ybbuhc ,llat A
”?thgir ,elihw a ni ti nekops t’nevah uoY“
.noitadipert htiw dellif kool a em evag mom yM
,detpurretni ylkciuq eh ”,enif s’ti ,oN“ ”...ot naem t’ndid I ,yrroS“ .flesym thguac I nehT
.stekramrepus gnikluh dna semoh rettuc eikooc fo sfeif nabrubus otni dedore em gniknalf sreparcsyks ytic cihtilagem eht yllautnevE
”.ereh emit emos llik em gnipleh er’uoY !enif s’tI“
”!nalp a ekil sdnuoS“
.em rof nepo rood eht dleh eh dna ni deklaw eW
,redrah dekrow ew tub ,rellams erew serutaef ruO
.sdrac elttil eht no erif yb dednuorrus stohs nootrac elttil erew erehT
”,thginot nwod gnisserd er’uoy ees I ,hO“
”?loohcs hgih ni slrig detad reven I woh wonk uoY“ .deddon I
”.syug uoy htiw ffuts od ot tnaw I ,haeY“
.efil ym fo syad tsom tius a erow I sraey neves tsal eht rof tnaem hcihw
.deilper eh ”,doog er’eW“
”.etarucca ytterp s’tahT“
.nwod ytitnedi oaL ym tel ev’I ekil leef tsuj I tub ,sseug I“
,pihsnoitaler ruo erofeb siht fo lla gnittup tpek I
erew ohw ,stiftuo gnihctam ni ssergit dna nexiv a yb dewollof sessalgnus dna yesrej llabtoof hsirag a gniraew rab eht deretne eh sa delley xof citcra egral a
”.did uoy tahw hguorht og ot em dellik ev’dluow ti kniht I
,hgU .deremmats I ”…saw gnivird ym ,dooG“
retlehs ruo tsniaga derettalps niar fo spord wef a sa kcurt eht ot dedaeh eW
.tnahcrem esion ,sfooW hcliZ yb uoy rof daeR
,evird eht morf ehcadaeh thgils a gnitteg saw I dna ,bmun gniog erew shgiht yM
.gnitegdif detrats I
.ecir ywehc eht htiw dedlem seiggev yhcnurc eht fo ssenhserf eht dna
”.retaw eht ni su nioj dna pu denaelc teG“
…ot eud ereh llits m’I naem I
,deksa eh ”?neeb elttaeS s’woh oS“
.tib a knus sredluohs dna srae siH
.ebohpomoh a ton er’uoy wonk I
”.esle gnihtemos tuoba klat nac ew ebyam
.dehgis dna knird rehtona koot eH
,dias I dna ,sdrow dnik sih ta em hguorht daerps
.yltneg dias eh ”,hO“
.desirprus yltnasaelp saw I dna elzzum ym ni lla ti deppop I
.stsal ti elihw ezies tsum eno taht
”?bat oN“ .dias droF
.hteet detniop ym revo emahs fo mlif a evael t’ndid osla tI
.deksa droF ”?ew llahS“
.og tel ew sa dias I ”,em ot doog sdnuoS“
.evird ot detnaw I naht erom owt saw ti tub ,sruoh owt tsuj saw ti ebyam ,yakO
.niarg eht tsniaga enog syawla dah I taht tsuj saw ti ebyam tub
.taorht ym ni gniwerb hgis rehtona tlef I
.denworf I neht dna ,syadiloh eht ekil detsat tI
”!emoh emocleW !noS“
.oidar on htiw yrenecs evititeper eht hguorht ekawa flesym peek ot yrt ot nac dnoces ym degguhc I ,sniatnuom eht dednecsa I sA
.deifirtcele gnieb erew yeht taht wohs ot seirrehc fo riap eht dnuora senil wolley deggaj htiw der dna eulb fo yarra hsirag a saw nac ehT
.smirt yklim htiw esuoh nomel ymaerc a was I taht
”?uoy htiw evil ot em tnaw yllaer uoy dluoW“ .dias I
.spot rieht ssorca srettel dlob ni ’stohS toH‘ htiw ecnartne eht raen sbat-llup wef a thguob eH
,oaL kaeps nac uoy fo htoB“
,swap rieht ni snac reeb htiw rehtegot gnimag-erp
,ecnarF tuoba nrael ot ereht tuo slairetam fo not a s’ereht tub
.stnerap ym morf dedivorp snoitanalpxe eht morf dna txetnoc morf ti fo tsom tog I tub ,dootsrednu I taht sdrow net yreve fo tuo eno saw tI
.tius dewollof dna secnalg degnahcxe selbat loop eht ta oud ehT .reev ezag sih gnittel tuohtiw tfel dna pu doots xof der rekib ehT
1 emuloV :ytisrufiD ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw ”gnildnikeR“ .ruoT dlroW
.dias eh ”,tsisni I tuB“
.meht dniheb deliart enohp sih morf gnos yrtnuoc muidats a gniralb tibbar a yltsal dna
”.knird nwo ym rof yap nac I“
.ti edam yletinifed stnerap ym dna
.niaga degguh su fo owt eht dna dias eh ”,won ereh er’uoY
”.em htiw siht gnirahs gnivah rof uoy knahT“ .deddon eH
”?syad eseht fo eno taht fo emos em ekam syug uoy naC“
enaitneiV fo ytic latipac eht morf saw mom yM
.revo emac rednetrab eht dna slaiceps knird rof unem eht hguorht decnalg I
”!ereh s’ytrap ehT“
ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.yldnik ffo ti devaw eH ”.enif s’tI“
.kcid a ekil dnuos ot gniyrt ton m’I ,yrroS“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.yrf rehtona eta dna ,deklus ,dehgis I
.C“ ,levon eht rof rotide na saw ooragnak der ehT
”.namreG ssenisub ym gnicitcarp dna swohs emag hsitirB gnignib sediseb skeew owt txen eht rof gnihtyna nalp t’ndid I ,eruS“
.dnuorgkcab eht ni sedacsaC eht htiw ytrap loop a ta elpoep gnuoy emos ot tuc yeht neht tub ,tseretni ym deuqip hcihw ,eldeeN ecapS eht fo tohs a saw erehT
dna pu gnimoc s’raeY weN oaL woh tuoba thguoht tsuj I“
.deksa droF ”?tesnus eht hctaw dna krap eht ot daeh annaW“ .nus gnittes eht ni egnaro nrut yks eht dehctaw ew elihw htron eht morf nwod gnidaeh sduolc krad sa
.ytinummoc gnitpecca ,egral a ot tuo emoc ot ysae si tI
.erots eht otni deklaw dna nib gnilcycer eht otni snac eht dessot I rac eht gnikcol retfA
.rood eht no lleb gnilgnaj eht yb detpurretni saw tar ehT ”,tub wonk I ,haeY“
”.ytefas nwo ym rof elpoep llet ot ton esiw ti dnif I erehw snoitautis llits era erehT
”?ecuas toh emos teg osla I naC“
.tnahcrem esion ,sfooW hcliZ yb uoy rof daer ,gnoS lA yb ”gnildnikeR“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.yako s’ti ,yeH“ ”.yrros m’I ,niagA“
.elpmis si tuo gnimoc taht emussa netfo
.ysub os s’ehs tluaf ruoy s’ti ekil ton s’ti os
,tra tae t’nac I dna ,ti ni yenom on s’ereht em gnillet tpek elpoep tsom
.yrt ot em rof lwob llams a ni rehtegot lla ti tup yehT
’,tnaw uoy boj eht rof sserd‘ dna ’,sseccus rof desserd eb
.ecaf railimaf eht ta delims I ”?droF“
,emosdnah siht gnitad saw eh tub ,ereht knim retaw ffub a tem I
,soaL morf seegufer erew stnerap ym fo htoB
.knird ym deppis I sa mih ot denrut I ”?pu s’tahW“
,rab eht ta nwod tas eW
.em fo tnorf ni ssalg eht ni gniremmihs diuqil nworb nedlog fo edahs mraw eht otni derats I
.enilosag fo semuf gnitaesuan eht htiw dexim ria niatnuom hserf fo htaerb a delahni I .sbmil ybbuts ,detartsurf ym hcterts ot noitats sag tsrif eht otni dellup I os ,knat retrauq a no gninnur saw I taht dewohs eguag leuf ehT
”.od ylniatrec yehT“
.em htiw pu ekorb xe ym yhw si sihT“ ”.yrros m’I“
?slliks oaL ym ot deneppah tahw ,hguoht ylsuoireS .ti yas ot yaw tcerroc eht saw tahT
,dias dna ,dewollaws
.deksa rednetrab eht
”.loohcs ruo ta nosrep yag ylno eht erew uoy taht os ti gnikaM“ ”?tahw roF“
”.nwot siht ni tsael ta
.meht fo derob teg I nehw rehtona ot boj eno morf dnuora gnitaolf neeb tsuj ev’I“ .ylteiuq dias eh
”.uoy htiw tuo emit ym rebmemer ot tnaw I ecnis ,thginot knurd teg ot tnaw t’nod I“
.tuo ti dehsif neht I
.seye sih gninediw deksa eh ”?ruls a ,ekil ,taht t’nsI“
.taht teg I loohcs htiw ysub er’uoY“
,hguot saw wohs eht gnidnatsrednU
seton surtic htiw dezinomrah taeh ehT
.og em tel eh sa dias eh ”,eciN“
.sknird eht no detrats teg ll’I neht ,wonk nehctik eht tel ll’I“
”.tellaw ym ni llits s’tI .dekool t’nevah I ,hO“
”,riaf s’taht ,thgirlA“
”.kaerb retniw gnirud niaga ylimaf tsoh ym detisiv I dna
.tcejbus eht egnahc ot evah t’ndid I dalg saw I dna
.etnioP muaB ot kcilbneohcS morf teg ot sruoh koot tI
.citamard saw ro looc dekool ti sa gnol sa thgir gnihtyna teg ot derac reven doowylloH esruoc fO
no enog dah yeht snoitacav eht tuoba em dlot stnerap ym elihw loohcs tuoba deklat I
.yliddig maws I retaw mrawekul eht otni gnippils retfA
”.dedeen I naht sessalc erom koot dna spihsnretni elpuoc a enod ev’I .loohcs fo sraey wef ysub a fo dnik neeb tsuj s’tI“
”.esaelp ,eci on dna ,em ot doog sdnuos tahT“
.tolgylop dna ,retirw ,naicisum a si ohw ,gnoS lA yb
syawlA‘ ,ekil sgniyas em otni deremmah tog yllaer ti loohcs hgih ni gnitekram koot I nehw dna
”.sgniht esoht nraeler t’nac uoy ekil ton s’tI“
”.tsrif eht er’uoy ,oN“
,uoy rof pu gnidnats rof seman em dellac yeht hguoht nevE
dna nwod dekool I ”,ti ni flesym gnisserpxe emit drah a dah syawla ev’I sseug I tub ,haeY“
”.seludehcs ruo ot eud s’ti niaga neht tub ,stnerap ym gniees tuohtiw syad og I semitemoS
.ylkciuq dias I ”,enif s’tI“
”.tnaw uoy fi sknird teg nac uoy dna ,sreziteppa dna slaem sevres taht rab a pu tih nac ew ,ees s’teL“
.deyojne I sknird ygrene wef eht fo eno saw ti tub
.soaL ni noitacav rieht dna ylimaf ees ot iiawaH ot spirt rieht tuoba yltsom
.tah rekcurt wolley rethgilhgih dna lennalf der sih ni tar eht deksa I ”?ruof rebmun no ytriht evah I yaM“
”.troppus ym evah uoy wonk uoY“
”,reganam selas a s’eh ,haeY“
,selbategev dedderhs eht fo hcnip a htiw gnola ecir emos pu dekcip I retfA
:dliuG eht morf selaT dna ,9 raoR ,8 gnaF :gnidulcni seigolohtna nezod a ni dehsilbup neeb sah lA .ranegaT yb ”.S.C.C“
”.kaerb gnirps no tsuJ“
.esuoh eht ni llits saw ti neht ereh emoh citauqa-non a ni loop a denwo enoemos fI
”?dub ,neeb uoy ev’woH“
.tnemetats tsal sih ta decamirg neht eH
”.ytisrevinU enakopS ot derrefsnart raey tsal etammoor ym ecnis ,tneduts rehtona htiw tnemtrapa na ni gnivil yltnerruc m’I dna ,raey siht roinuj a m’I ,haeY“
,hU“ .oaL ot hsilgnE morf yltcerid sgniht etalsnart ot ton flesym dnimer ot dah I
”.enim fo ytitnedi eguh rehtona s’ti ecnis
.seirf emos dereffo dna em ot etalp eh dehsup eH
.deksa ooragnak der eht
tuo emoc ot ecnahc eht eb yam
.emoh kcab em detnaw yllaer stnerap ym tub
aibrubus fo senal enihtnirybal eht hguorht semit elpuoc a gninrut retfa setunim wef a ylno saw tI
.nehctik eht fo aera gninid eht ot yawllah eht nwod delddap I sa edutilimisirev ot tnorffa eht ffo denrut dna etomer defoorpretaw eht debbarg I
.yaw emas eht em taert dluow elpoep diarfa saw I tub
.retaw fo tuo gnieb ot desu tog I tub ,devil su ekil sklof ynam erehw
,remmus tsal nilreB ni margorp daorba yduts a gniod osla saw I
.boj siht rof taht od ot ton denrael ev’I“
”.sgnileef ytliug ym tuoba nepo eb em gnittel dna nepo gnieb rof uoy gniknaht eb dluohs I“ ”.uoy knahT“
”.fo dnik ,haeY“ .kcab gnihctiws niaga deksa mom ym ”?yrgnuh uoy era ,thgirlA“
”.uoy knaht ,haey oS
,lleW“ ”.snossel ratiug ruoy ot drawrof dekool syawla uoy dna ssalc dnab devol uoY
,gnikcal fo dnik era seirarbil ytisrevinu eht nevE“
.deksa I ”?deneppah tahW“
.mih ta daeh ym dekcoc tsuj I
,retal litnu ezilaer ro wonk t’nod elpoep emoS
.lennalf dna pac sih ni llits saw eH
.noitces ydnac dna spihc eht rof dedaeh dna ni deklaw flow ylredle na sa ecnartne eht ot ezag sih deppans eH
.kcurt cihtilonom eht otni deppoh I dna revo dellup eh retfa pop a draeh I .egnaro ymaerd
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”?ytriht-neves ta ecalp ruoy morf pu uoy kcip I tuoba woH“
”.doof rof regnuh I“ .gnorw saw tahT
.suonotonom emaceb lla ti emit fo tnuoma yldoog a rof meht hguorht gnivird retfa tub ,lufituaeb ylbidercni saw tI
.nwod yaw sti no denrub yeksihw nomannic eht sa eugnot ym delkcit seton egnaro dna yrrehc teewsrettib ehT
dias I ”,uoy egduj t’now yletinifed I ?ti si tahW“
,suoigiler ylurt reven saw dad ym tub
.gnittup-ffo eb dluoc noitcaer rallod-noillim eht ecnis ,emas eht noisserpxe ym tpek tsuj I
,dias dna htaerb peed a koot eH
.drawrof gnivom tpek uoy tub ,egabrag ekil uoy detaert elpoeP
.dias droF ”,regrub ollebotrop a dna em rof reeb toor a tsuJ“
,soaL rof ffuts ecnerefer fo tol a t’nsi ereht taht gniyas uoy rebmemer I dna
”.thginot uoy taert em teL !skcub ytnewT
”.em ot gniklat deppots ehs ,oN“
.kcab evird ruoh owt dna ereht evird ylkeew sruoh owt eht fo derit tog mom ym dna
”.sgnileef ym truh ot tnaw t’nod uoy esuaceb ,dnopser dluohs uoy fi erus ton er’uoy tub ,citamelborp ro tnarongi gnihtemos dias I syas taht eno ehT“
htmraW ”?thginot tuo gnah ot tnaw uoy od
.niaga reve ereht ni wap a tes reven ot em detnaw ohw
ti enod evah ohw esohT
.tnemhsilbatse eht otni tnew yllautca reven I tub ,ti nees syawla dah I
”.eulb eht fo tuo em htiw pu ekorb eh neht dna raey a rof yug a detad I .elgnis m’I ,on dnA
.drow tsal eht ta delims I ”.adnik
.elims a htiw dias I ”,taht htiw thgirla naht erom m’I ,haeY“
”.em ot doog sdnuoS“
…dna semalf delaever serauqs owt tsrif ehT
.deksa eh ”?reilrae morf drac hctarcs eht morf gnihtyna teg uoy diD“
”.syug uoy htiw naitoaL ni kaeps ot tnaw I taht yas ot gniyrt m’I“
.dalas ayapap dah yeht sa em rof ecir deirf eiggev dexim emos pu devres stnerap yM
.eugnot ym no noitasnes gninrub eht etaba depleh hcihw ,notrac a morf klim yos deneteews emos htiw nwod ti dehsaw I
.dehgis eh ”,krow ot kcab teg ot deen I kniht I“
.dehgis eh ”…tsuj I tub ,sknahT“
.pis rehtona koot dna dias I ”,gnikniht tsuj ,hO“
.ngis ’etnioP muaB ot emocleW‘ nedoow ,derehtaew eht tih d’I litnu setunim elpuoc rehtona ylno saw ti lufknaht saw I tub
.yldethgiled pu til seye nedlog sih dna redluohs sih revo dekool tnadnetta ehT
”.nommoc ni sgniht emos tog ev’ew kniht I ,lleW“
’.llirG dna raB s’tnerB‘ dellac ecalp a ot evord eW
”.erutluc nwo ym ot semoc ti nehw egdelwonk ni gnikcal m’I hcum woh
fo dnik I ecnis ,pohs riaper otua eht morf derif fo dnik saw I
.denoihsaf dlo ym fo pis a koot I dna ,sknird ruo pu devres ooragnak evaus eht nooS
”.erom evah nac yletinifed uoY“
.mih erussaer ot gniyrt dias I ”,etal oot reven s’ti ,yeH“
,tsewhtroN cificaP eht fo ytisrevinU eht ta sloop eht fo eno pu tih d’I neht miws ot gnihca yllaer saw I fI
”.rallod a ylno s’ti dna ,yenom ym s’tI“
”.tner ekam em gnipleh t’nera stnerap ym ekil ton s’ti niaga neht tub
”.etsaw ot og ot taht tnaw t’nod eW .oot ,ecir deirf eht tae woN
.niaga nwod dekool I
OT tuo gnimoc era uoy OHW no erom sdneped ti yas yam
.em degguh dna deksa eh ”?yrgnuh uoy erA“
.tar llat eht ot kcab etalp eht dehsup dna dias I ”,efil ym fo sraey neves tsal eht detsaw ev’I ekil leef I dna ,sgniht sgnorw eht gnizitiroirp peek tsuj I“
”!iad oal kap oah ,mmh ,oaH !ti gnad ,hu ,oaH !oB“
”.redistuo na ekil ssel neve leef I won naem I“
.oaL ni dias dad ym
”.reverof ni uoy nees t’nevah I“
.yltnalahcnon dias eh ”,heM“ ”.emahs a s’tahT“
.ecaps llams a rof evisserpmi etiuq saw llaw eht dniheb selttob fo noitcelloc ehT
.syadiloh s’yrtnuoc eht fo yna rof gnihtyna did reven I yltnecer dna
ecnis ,loop roodtuo na ni gnimmiws srotca eht dewohs yeht elihw elttaeS ni ecalp ekat seivom ees ot gniredliweb syawla saw tI
.snoom gniwolg dna snus dezilyts htiw denozalbme sknurt miws egnaro fo riap a ni tog dna ,derewohs ,moor ym ni egaggul ym dessot I
,em trofmoc hcrats mraw eht tel dna elzzum ym ni eno deppop neht I
.yrtnuoc eht dnuora tuo daerps lla ev’ew sseug I“
”.nalp fo tros emos pu ekam nac eW
.ylthgit em degguh mom ym
”?retfa yad eht gnihtyna od syug uoy diD“
.dloc teg annog s’doof ruoY“
.dias rednetrab eht ”,gniht eruS“
”.meht ot sgniht cisab yas ot woh togrof I dna ,oaL ni stnerap ym ot gniklat deirt I yadot emoh tog I nehw ekil ,naem I
,moor ym ni enola swohs hctaw dna potpal ym no teg tsuj ot detpmet saw em fo trap a rennid retfA
dehgis eh ”,ykcul taht lla ton er’eW“
”?tahW“ .ecaf dna eciov sih dellif nrecnoC
.yrettol eht now tsuj ehs ekil detca ehs dna dneirf a dlot I nehw saw ylniatrec tI
.yenruoj doog a saw ti
.dluoc I ssalc sronoh dna PA yreve koot dna ,maet sinnet eht denioj ,loohcs hgih ni bulc yreve did I
.esnecil ym dna rac a tog I tsael ta tub ,raey gnitnioppasid a saw xis dnasuoht owT
.unem eht no ti ot gnitniop deksa I ”’?hpargotohP gninruB‘ a s’tahW“
”?doog ton knird eht sI“
.tnaw uoy fi pleh ot yrt nac I“
”.stnerap rieht morf pleh gnitteg ro emoh ta gnivil rehtie era wonk I elpoep tsoM“ .dias eh ”,haeY“
.su dniheb rettahc dna ,shgual ,sknilc eht tsgnoma teiuq deniamer tsuj droF
.nwod doof sih tup dna em ot resolc denael eH
.semalf ni deflugne saw taht retupmoc a ta gnipyt etoyoC a fo lebal a htiw elttob egral a ot kcab bmuht sih detniop eh
.enim saw seitenin eht morf iasaK dlo rieht em dlot yeht neht dna
.dalas fo lwob llams eht ffo gnihsilop retfa dlot saw I sa did I
,boj rieht sa evol yeht gnihtemos gniod enoemos fo elpmaxe emirp a si mom ym neht dna“ ,dias eh
.enif s’tI“ ”.deksa I tegrof tsuJ
.sretto dewalc-llams rehto owt eht was dna rood eht denepo I sa dias I ”,emoh m’I ?olleH“
.naicisum a emoceb ot detnaw uoy dias uoy thguoht I“
,sulP .enobmort eht ro ratiug eht htiw saw taht rehtehw
.mih fo tnorf ni decalp saw seirf fo edis a htiw regrub eiggev a sa deksa droF ”?gnorw s’tahW“
erehw ,tfihs artxe na no koot I esuaceb ytrap yadhtrib tsrif-ytnewt s’dneirf a dessim neve I ,hgu ,eurt s’tahT“ ”.raey roines eritne ruoy dna raey roinuj ruoy fo tser eht evah llits uoY“
.gnabarpgnauL fo ytic nrehtron eht morf saw dad ym dna
.driB gninthgiL maoR ,wolley ,wen ,keels a ta gnirats saw I dlofdnilb eht ffo koot yeht nehW
.trihs ym ton dna skcals ym no dednal ti yllufknaht
”.hairap laicos a emoceb uoy neht ,ezigolopa ot liaf uoy fi dna ,hturt eht s’tI“
”.tuo gninnur s’emit ekil leef I dna
”.oga emit gnol a pu taht evag fo tros I
.yrf rehtona eta dna dehgis eh ”,did I“
”,etammoor wen a rof gnikool ma I“
.daeh ym fo kcab eht dehctarcs I sa dias I ”,yrros m’I .wonk I“
”.eurt yletinifed s’taht ,haeY“
enohp ym no edistuo gnitiaw saw I neves denrut ti nehW
ti enod ton evah ohw esohT  .yrruFoS dna
.yletelpmoc draob eht dessim yeht nehw desruc sreyalp trad eht fo eno sa dehgis rednetrab ehT
.esuoh ym ni gnimmiws og ot deticxe pal sih no pot knat dna sknurt miws sih htiw taes regnessap eht ni droF derebmemer I
.hguoht taht tsuj naht erom s’ti dna
.retsiger eht dniheb oerets egnaro thgirb eht morf deralb gnos kcor seitenin etal yreif A
.laed emit eno a tsuj erew ti hsiw adnik I“ ”.no
saw tI“ ”!uoy knahT .doog ytterp s’ti ,haeY“
,gniyas er’yeht tahw dnatsrednu t’now uoY“
.guh mraw a ti gnivig erew I fi sa swap htob htiw ssalg eht dezeeuqs I
.em fo tnorf ni wap a devaw I
”.loohcs hgih gnirud ereh fo tuo teg ot dedeen yllaer I ,haey tub ,retal ti nialpxe ll’I“
.ti ekam nac uoy wonk I“
”.uoy rof siht fo noisrev nairategev a pu pihw nac eW“ .deksa dad yM ”?emos tnaw yllaer uoy oD“
.llew sa slliks gnitirw dna gnidaer ym no krow ot dah yletinifed I
.rood ssalg eht tuo gnikool
,ecnarF morf yllacirotsih s’ylimaf ym ,lleW“
.retniw eht ni eno-ytnewt denrut I
.reeb toor sih otni gnikool ylwols deksa eh
.thgiled ni hsiws liat sih was I tub
2 fo 1 traP ,gnoS lA yb
.hctam reccos a gnihctaw retaw eht ni saw dad ym sa liame na gnidaer retupmoc eht ta gnittis mom yM
”.trams er’uoy wonk I .em htiw clac PA koot uoY
.yltneg dias I ”,yako ,hO“
”.droF ,borp ton s’tI“
.setangoc emos tuo kcip ot elba saw I ylgnisirprus dna ,pu peek ot tseb ym did tub
.noitalosi ni redrah hcum eb nac tI
og sevil ruo sa gniod peek ew gnihtemos s’tI
.ylgnirussaer dias tar eht ”,thgirla s’tI“
.retteb on yletinifed m’I .taht yas t’noD“ ”…dlihc dab a m’I“
,ytinummoc oaL eht ot detcennoc erom tlef ew nehw semit eseht gnirud saw tI
.deksa dad ym ”?su htiw arepo paos iahT a hctaw ot tnaw uoy erus uoy erA“
”.doof tae ot tnaw I ,hu ,m’I
.tiftuo ym ot gninoitom elihw gninnirg dias eh
.sdnarb rouqil dna sreeb tnereffid rof ecaps da na yllacisab erew sllaw ehT
.sremmargorb dna seippuy eht lla htiw ,edistsae eht no kcilbneohcS ni ti evah ot dah ew esruoc fO
.efil ym fo tser eht rof emoh ta gnivil em htiw looc era dadpets dna mom ym tsael tA .thgirla s’tI“
”.semit wef a kcolc mrala ym tes ot togrof
.deksa ooragnak eht ”?bat a pu nepo ot tnaw uoy fo owt eht oD“
.guh thgit a em evig ot retnuoc eht dnuora nar eh sa detuohs eh ”!gnol os neeb s’ti ,eilrahC“
”.elpoep reeuq dna ,erutluc ,sgnidliub yb dednuorrus m’I tsael ta tub ,yniaR .ereh ekil tsuJ“
,elttaeS ni neve ,sklof citauqa rof dengised syawla t’nerew stnemtrapA
”.ecalp a fo wonk I“
.oga shtnom elpuoc a ereh gnikrow detrats I .ereh gnivil llitS .hcum gnihton ,hO“
,oaL kaeps ot edur saw ti meht dlot esle enoemos dna ,rehtegot oaL gnikaeps erew yeht nehw mih tsniaga gnittolp erew yeht thguoht sreganam eht fo eno dias mom yM
.yawevird eht ni dekrap I sa em revo dehsaw aiglatson mraw fo esnes A
”.erehwyna ylppa t’ndid I taht tluaf nwo ym s’ti ,yltsenoH“
”.secnatsmucric suoirav
.em ta daeh reh dekcoc dna hsilgnE ni dias mom ym ”,oaL ni kaeps ot elba era ew ,sey ,lleW“ .deremmats I
.soaL ni deneppah taht stneve lanoitidart dna larutluc ot emac ti nehw yllaicepse
.flesym ot tuo gnimoc neve emit drah a dah I loohcs hgih nI“
’,woN pU‘ dellac elpoep tsom hcihw
,gniht a saw egelivirp ssalc taht ro msilatipac htiw smelborp yna was ohw loohcs ssenisub eht ni wef eht fo eno saw I ekil demees syawla tI
.sretto rehto eht morf tnereffid dekool yletinifed ew dna ,nwot eht ni sretto dewalc-llams ylno eht erew su fo eerht ehT
.em dednuorrus enots fo sllaw gnisopmi dna seert tnadrev sa strap rieht fo mus eht otni detcurtsnoced erew esoht hguone nooS
,seirekab elpitlum snur dna snwo mom ruoY“
.tuo snrut yenruoj tuo gnimoc s’droF fo gninnigeb eht woh dna rehtegot gnineve rieht fo tser eht etagivan droF dna eilrahC woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
”?thgir ,krow rof tol a slevart dadpets ruoy dias uoY
.etnioP muaB ekil ,erehwon fo elddim eht ni pu gniworg eno ylno eht saw I ekil demees ti ecnis ,sselpleh dna enola tlef ohw elpoep reeuq rehto pleh ot saw laog rehtonA
.ezag sih detreva dna dias eh ”,uoy llet ot detnaw I esle gnihtemos s’erehT“
emit emos evah uoy fi tub ,ysub ylbaborp er’uoy wonk I ,yeH“
.deksa I ”?sehsid oaL emos kooc ot woh em hcaet uoy naC“
,tuo gnikaerf saw I
.yawyna tnew ew nehw no gniog saw tahw dootsrednu yllaer reven I
.rovalf ’ygrenE fo krapS‘ etirovaf ym syawla saw yrrehC
,seciohc ym tuoba suoicsnoc erom eb dna ynapmoc rellams a morf gnihtemos gniknird neeb ev’dluohs ylbaborp I
”.meht otni ton m’I esuaceb s’tahT“
”.elbmag t’nod I wonk uoY“ .ti rof diap dna
”gnildnikeR“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
!seY“ ,demialcxe eh neht dna sdrac sih fo wef a hguorht tnew droF ”.resol a s’eniM“
.knird ym ffo dehsilop I sa xob a rof deksa neht tar ehT
.sreksihw ym kcab gnidneb em dessik dna guh gib a em evag ehs sa deksa mom ym ”?yrgnuh uoy erA ?evird eht saw woH“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.delkcuhc neht dna dias eh ”,notgnihsaW fo etatS eht fo egaugnal laiciffo eht si ygolopa eht wonk uoY“
”.yrros yllaer m’I“
”gnildnikeR“   yojne esaelP
.wenk I nosrep tsevarb eht erew uoy tuB“
.esuoh s’tnerap ym rof ffo koot dna nades der yrrehc ,dlo ym ni kcab tog dna mih ta devaw I enod saw I nehW
”.taht raeh ot yrros m’I“
.ecitsuj emos sklof naciremA-oaL rehto dna meht od ot detnaw I dna
,oot ytinummoc eht tuo gnipleh yllautca dna
”.rof diap si esuoh ehT
pup retto na sa rellams neve saw I nehW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
em rof tekcit ffo hctarcs ’kaertS toH‘ a pu gnar neht
”.tniop laer on s’ereht ebyam os
.yaw siht gnidaeh saw wenk I eno on tub ,em ynapmocca ot enoemos evah ot ecin neeb ev’dluow tI
,tnemeganam tiforpnon dna noitartsinimda ssenisub ni gnirojam elbuod saw I
,dias dna dewollaws eH
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
,uoy tcetorp ot detnaw I dna
”.taht htiw looc er’uoy gnisseug m’I“
.mih ees dluow taht em dna stnerap ym tsuj saw ti hguoht neve thgiew sih tuoba suoicsnoc-fles tlef yllausu eH
,tnatropmi ytterp gnihtemos uoy llet ot ereh uoy gnitivni yllanigiro saw I ,lleW“
.repap fo teehs a no gnihtemos delbbircs eh sa dias eh ”,ces a tsuj ,eruS“ .tseuqer ym detaeper dna dehguoc I os cisum eht revo em raeh t’ndid ylbaborp eH