,niaga elims tahT
.doow eb ot ti rof ybbonk dna dnuor oot era
ollenurB fo sessalg owt sredro ekidpU dna
,esopxe ot sgniht suoicerp kees htob eW .stif fo dnik tI“
”?emoc uoy evah raf woH“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.doog rof pils eht em nevig t’nsah eh gnidivorp
.selur sih ,eciohc siH
dneirfyob ro lrig ydaets a evah t’nac ohw esle ydobyna ekil sdeen htiw tibbar elam yhtlaeh a m’I“
.tey dimaryp kcits-daerb ym ot detcaer dah ydobyna fi ees ot dnuora gnikool ,tsrif ta ti ekat t’nod I
,deb tevlev a no ,ti nI
,scileR“   yojne esaelP
,mih tuoba ot deklat ev’I elpoep eht lla dnA
.diletsum elttil ,mih teg og woN
.wap s’ekidpU ni gniht revlis ehT
,mih ni tseretni s’def eht gnidrager stcaf tsenoh eht wenk I
,meht rof krow did uoY
”?htraE no nosrep detnaw tsom eht uoy era yhW ?ti si tahw oS
”.straeH fo gniK eht erew uoy
ton m’I“ .enim teem seye siH
.tnemezama ni ta sknilb eh taht tcejbo eno morf kcab ylluferac gnidnats esroh a ,ereh pu nosrep rehto eno ylno si erehT
,opmaC eht otni syaw ruoF .deen ll’I lla s’tI
.ruoh siht ni em sevig eh tahw htiw eliforp tneced a rof hguone teg ll’I fi gniklat mih deen ll’I .gnikcit s’kcolC
modnaF yrruF eht ni skrow nezod wef a dehsilbup sah ohw ,floW pilS yb
.em tsurt ,deef siht gnihctaw t’nera od ohw esoht dnA
.daed uoy tnaw lla retsinim tenibac naissuR a ,tcepsus I
.em tcetorp ot dib a ni
.siht yas ot yaw ysae on s’ereht
.oot sriatsnwod si aremac yM“
.tsenrae ssel elttil a emit siht
…meht rof sretupmoc kcah ot stcartnoc rieht koot uoY“
,won thgir ytic eht ni moor dellif-ecnallievrus tsom eht ylbaborp si sihT“ .sffins ekidpU
sdne eht ezilaer I sa knilb I
,ekidpU si siht oS
.pukooh ruo ot seulc eht degnarra dna enil no tcartnoc ym tuo dekcip eh ecnis neeb sah
,gnirettahc elpoep tsuJ
.flesmih tcelloc ot dah eh taht esiugsid ot eniw eht fo pis dehsur rehtona koot eH
.osserpse dna ,etalocohc
,dnuof eb ot tnaw t’nod ohw ebolg eht dnuora elpoep fo snezod gnisahc ylsseltneler retfa
”,dellik neeb evah dluoc uoy …uoY“ ”?thgir
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.eit-kcen elbisivni na gnitsujda
.oga sraey ytxis revo srorroh sih fo ekaw eht ni
.ylkaew sreffo ekidpU ”,hcum ytterP“
,opmaC led azzaiP eht revo rewol gnitteg si nus ehT
.toof sih no walc a sffucs eH
…yad rieht niur ot gniog saw ydobemos stegrat rieht nraw ot segassem tnes ,yenom eht koot
”.taht naht erom uoy ewo I“
”.revetahw ro htnom ro raey eht fo retroper uoy gnikam dna
,krow noitarotser doirep devreserp-llew emos ees I
.doog yllaer s’yap eht sselnu
,seirots rehto oN
.sesirprus rehto emos sa llew sa
,ognoC eht ni noitpurroc fo erusopxe ym tuoba wonk uoY
”.ecnedifnoc elttil a dna
.esenapaJ eht tsuj t’nsi tI  ?yhW“
,desopxe neeb dah snis fo gnir esohw seilimaf noil dna aneyh esoht llefeb tahw yltcaxe dnatsrednu dna elcitra ym daer uoy fI
;ylthgils gnibbe si taeh ehT
.em tem neve t’ndah eh dnA
.ekil I smetsys emaG
,diputs s’taht kniht dna daeha oG
,ezeirf detnalpsnart ot ssalg-niats ot eutats morf evom ylkciuq I sA
,otohp a ekat em tel ll’eh luftbuod s’tI
od elpoep sgniht dab eht gnisopxe taht detartsnomed uoy
.esnes on sekam tI .rehtie
.redluohs ym revo retiaw eht ot sdon eh sa rae na skcoc eH
.yllautca otno dloh ot egami ysae rehtar a s’ti dna
.mih ta nworf I
…uoy nehw taht si
.krow rehto oN .sweivretni on
,ycnaN ,emag a neeb syawla sah efil yM .seY“
,raf os retroper a steg ylno skool dooG“
,hcihw fo gnikaepS
.eof sseltneler rieht htiw dnetnoc
,dlot eb ot yrots hcum os llits s’erehT
;uoy rof noitseuq eno tsuj tog ev’I“
,boj eht no sraey ym ni evitarugif dna laretil htob
.gninnur fo tol a seod ekidpU
.edis dab rieht no em tog tahw ton s’taht tub
”.og ti tel ot gnilliw m’I
,rettum I ”,dratsaB“
”?ereht nwod redrocer ym si
.won enog saw elims siH
gnol siH ”.gnidrocer dnuos on s’ereht epoh I hguoht
.sdneirf ekam ot ekil I
elbat eht no spihc eht htiw eno eht m’I
.em hpargotohp t’nod esaelP“
.dezingocer I mohw azalp eht ssorca ydobemos saw ereht yas tsuj s’tel dna
”?gnihtemos ro ytirahc ot lla ti evig uoy diD
,sdnoces wef eseht fo ecaps eht nI
.sroodtuo thgirb eht ot ecnartne eht ta em tsap gnizag erofeb nikpan delwarcs rehtona em sdnah eH
.dniwnu ot deen I ,yeH“
.denworf ekidpU ”.sevink rO“
.gnorw siht nettog evah t’nac I
”.em no nwod tnew revres ym nehw efac tenretnI na ni knird a gnivah saw I“
,teg thgim yeht esuac
,elims ot seirt ylkaew eH
.raef a ton ,won regna na s’ti tub ,suoixna m’I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.aremac rehtona uoy yub ll’I  .ti evaeL“
.moor sciler eht ot roolf a pu og s'teL .ereh toN“
,redluohs ym ta hcuot tfos eht erofeb em dniheb htaerb eht raeh I
,won dna ereh thgir
,ylegnarts dna seye sih ni rewsna ot ecnatculer a ees nac I
,ekidpU htiw enola yllatot gnieB
.desirprus neve ton m’I ,lleH
.ynomerec no dnats ton s’teL
seod oS“  .sgurhs dna nihc sih rednu ruf eht hctarcs ot sesuap eH
,dna scilbuper ananab owt ,aifaM eht ,sgnoT ehT
.eil evitaerc a rof gnikool
yats nac I sa netfo sa thgis ni yats ot woh wonk I
dehsilbup yllanigiro saw yrotS ralucitrap sihT
,aignaM led arroT eht fo wodahs evissam eht gniggard
.selkcunk ydoolb dna stius evisnepxe htiw shtapoicos hcir yb eromyna deyalp teg t’nod tsuj I  .syawla
,tnemom a tsuj roF
,tfel seye sih gnillor erofeb
dnoces tilps a rof siht rednop I ”.yrruh dna
,mih tsniaga evom yna taht ezilaer I
,dellik ydobemos tog I  ?rettam ti seoD“
?taht od nac I kniht t’nod uoY“  .truh tsenrae
,desuma tsomla
,won syad rof seulc em gnideef neeb s’eH
.mih tops ot seganam ekidpU dna ,aneiS ni nug derih A  .timmaddoG ”.ecnedicnioc
,angoloB ni spohs derettuhs eht no itiffarg dedoc eht dna
ecno ta lla em stih tI
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.serutplucs devrac rof sdnats rinevuos eht esurep dna
.won mih hctac ot gniog ton m’I ezilaer tub
.sterger sih dnuora elims yls a gnivruc ecaf sih
”.ekidpU ,olleH“ .napdaed I
.eye eulb lufelab a em sevig dna dnoces a rof aremac eht srewol
.od I sa eenk sih gnihsurb liat ym
,rehtegot seulc sih gnittup ytluciffid eht lla htiW
”.laer saw em dlot tsuj uoy tahw fo hcum woh wonk neve t’nod I“
.teprac gnicuder-dnuos eht no gnilffuhs teef yffulf
.ekil kool I tahw wonk t’nseod IBF ehT“
ruoh flah tsal eht ni sevom sih lla gnireenigne neeb yllaretil sah tibbar siht taht
.yzarc m’I ekil em ta skool eH ”?tahW“
,gnol steg ecaf s’tibbar
”.krow ruoy ot eit ot seititnedi tahw wonk ot tnaw I esuaceb ksa ylno I“
.gniyzzid tsuj s’ti
”.llew hpargotohp uoy evorp nac I tub
otacreM azzaiP eht ot htuos deirruh s’eH
.hcraes elgooG a htiw pu nrut ot drah si ecaf ym dna
,mih tem tsuj ev’I hguoht
.trap drah eht syawla si gnitiaW
,snoitasrevnoc nwo rieht ni debrosba era su dnuora selbat ehT
eht dna ,wol spils aremac ehT
”.truh steg ydobon
,dnim ym ni egami delzzum-trohs ,dewaj-mils sih peek I
.nus gnikeep-duolc eht morf mraw llits si tlep nworb ym
,ecneitap htiw elbaod si gnihtyrevE“
.siht ekil gnihtemos no delbmag t'nevah I
?yb enog uoy evah sesaila ynam woh oS“
saremac tuohtiw ecalpemos mih teg
,tsrif ta eil a devil I
..moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
.erehwemos og ot sah noisneT
,arroT eht fo sotohp gnikat tibbar a sah elbat gnirobhgien A
,ozzallaP eht fo dworc gnineve eht otni ffo seirruh dna snrut eH
.tibbar si llems nac I llA
raef tsniaga flesym gninoh ot detacided neeb evah noisseforp dna efil yM
,deneppah taht retfa oS“
,era ew erehw ot pu gnihctac noitautis eht fo ytilaer eht
”.ti rof nar dna seitirohtua lacol ot sgninraw tnes I neht dna
— gip tsixes a ,taehc a
”.evael nac ew litnu ybraen ecalp efas a ot su teg nac I
,dereffo gnieb noitanissassa dna ,tfeht
,stekcop sih ni swap ,aremac ot aremac morf skool eh sa leviws srae
?stnemyap-nwod dna sreniater eht lla htiw od uoy did tahW
”.noitcelloc ruoy rof rehtonA .ereH
,stnempihs lacidem rieht dih snoitazinagro dia erehw wonk ot detnaw yehT“
,ti otni erats I sa elbat ym no ssalg retaw eht ssorca sllaf maebnus A .em …dna
,etib rehtona sekat dna wap sih ni kcitsdaerb eht ta serats ekidpU  ”.meht od t’ndid I dnA“ “—yeht dluow yhw
.eudrevo etunim A
?etoyoc suoredrum siht ot flesmih dewohs ohw tibbar eht tuoba od ot tahw
.troffe htiw evitcejbo gnipeek ,yas I ”,no emoC“
?arrezaJ-lA .nwod mih denruT
,saw tnuts eht sa looc sA
.daed em tnaw dluow yeht yhw enigami dluoc taht gnidaer ydobyna ,llew
.serutnevdasim esoht fo yna ni em retfa nissassa na dah reven ev’I
”?tser a taht evig uoy dluoc ,tcaf nI
,ni peerc ot gnitrats si yteixnA
.ésopxe gnikaerb yna
.pu em sezis eh sa elkraps lufhtuoy a yb dedraug seye eulb esoht nihtiw snoitome eurt eht
.og mih tel I dnA
.elbuort eht htrow os ro
.secnatsmucric rehto yna rednu srae ym ot hsulb a gnirb dluow esiarp siH .pu sdnats eH
”.meht od t’nod dna
,drawoc a saw eh em dlot yehT .mih tuoba deil
,hsif reggib a m’I
,hgih seirots lareves hcra sllaw ehT
?gniog uoy era erehW“
,sladnacs ,noitamrofni no nwod gnitib ,toohs ot desoppus ton m’I secalp ni gnitoohs
.og mih tel I retfa noos os
stohs gnirapmoc era ohw revo selbat ruof elpuoc noil a gnidulcni
.siht ekil snoitautis ni melborp a semitemos si liat yM
.noitacol suomynona na ni nwod-tis a rof srallod noillim a em dereffo
.ereh si nissassa eht
,mih knaht dluohs I
.elpoep lufrewop wef a detnioppasid tsuj dah ekidpU ,saw droW
,rethgit dna redloc sworg moor ehT
.elims yhtoot a htiw syas eh
.ti rof drow eno saw fierG
.won gnipmup si traeh yM  ”?miH“ ”.mih …saw tI
.ti no sweivretni rehto on evah I dalg m’I dna
”?ereh ni weivretni ruo gnihsinif ew era yhw oS“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”.rotarepo ercoidem a rof eltit cireneG“
…tsuj I .deyonna ton m’I“
”?uoy t’nevah ,emit ruoy ni senob wef a pu denrut ev’uoy dna
.sehsinav eh erofeb tuo ekam t’nac I taht ria eht ni revlis gnihtemos sevaw eH
.etirovaf a saw eson eht tub ,tsenoh eb ot
.tuo siht gnitset m’I“
,elbissop sa mih ot esolc sa dnatS
naht erom elttil a sedih seye sih ni kool ehT
.gnol taht rof em tcetorp ot gniyrt neeb s’eh snaem hcihw
.ecnerolF ni eceipretsam s’ihcsellenurB retfa ylatI ni lardehtaC demoD tsegral dnoces eht
,stnemele eht fo tuo derots era lardehtac eht fo stnenopmoc larutcetihcra ,edisnI
.detseuqer sa dimaryp a ni pu skcits daerb eerht eht dnats I  .won si emit ehT
uoy ot tnemaciderp ym gnillips rof em ot ti ewo uoy leef I
,ydobemos rof gnitiaw ylraelc er’uoy esuaceb uoy rehtob ot tnaw t’nod I ,lleW“
”?ti llac I dluohs tahW“
.reverof ereh yats t’nac eW“
.ti no egassem eht daer ot revo ti nrut I
.ylsuoires ekat nac I siht fo hcum woh tuo erugif ot yrt I sa smiws daeh yM
.pohs otaleg eht edistuo pu eueuq
”?nug a tog s’eh fI ?thgir ,edistuo eb ot sah eH“
,ruomarap ’sessob azukaY eht htiw tpels I“
”sdeR nacsuT dna ,stibbaR ,scileR“
”.ycnaN ,elpoep htiw doog ton m’I naem t’nseod sretupmoc margorp I esuac‘ tsuJ
.ni sknis lla ti sa gnikniht tuohtiw pis rehtona ekat I
.ozzalaP eht fo tuo sgnidliub eht neewteb gnisir selbboc eht ,tsew daeh dna snoitcerid sih wollof I
.tiaw I sa nikpan a rednu dih redrocer
”.seirtnuoc ynam ni ytilaturb ecilop otni ésopxe ym dna
”.siht eveileb t’nac I
.noitnetta lluf sih teg dna
”.ruoh na em desimorp uoY
.hcum oot eb ot gnitteg saw sihT  .knilb I
”.tseb ym ta m’I nehw s’tahT“
.levon tsrif sih gnitide won si dna
.ezeerb thgils eht ni gnirettulf waj sih rednu zzuf eht
.gnipleh ton s’taht ,yrroS“
,nosiop eb t’now ti ,dnuof m’I fI .deirrow
”.oot taht rof llew yap I  .xes
.noitnetta sih nward sah tahw ees ot dnuora strad ezag yM
;llew yllaer ytic siht wonk I
,elpoep dab eht llA
”.dehpargotohp eb ton rehtar dluow
”.eniw enif nmad emos saw ti timda ot evah uoY
,reve emit tsrif eht roF
.kool ot desoppus ton m’I secalp ni
naht erom raf tellub a devresed dna
,skoob nepo rieht no mih dah sesirpretne lanimirc emos dna
.pmuls sredluohs siH
,pu roolf eno dna retal etunim a naht sseL .rettum I
,erauqs eht fo stohs
,niaga em si tohs txeN
,etoyoC triD yb daer
?noitcerid degnahc
.wonk t’ndluohs I elpoep htiw eb t’ndluohs I secalp ni sgniht
ekil smees tahw ni sllaf ecaf siH
.omouD eht ot ti gninioj llaw retuo gnol a tfel yrutnec htneetruof eht ni lardehtac eht ot noisnetxe deliaf a erehw
egnirc a no gniredrob hsulb
.dluoc I skrowten elohssa-live dna lanimirc eht lla otni teg ot sPI emos defoops dna sesaila emos edam ,dnuorgrednu tnew I  .did yehT“
.sdworc yad-etal eseht ni elbissopmi hgin neeb evah dluow mih gnihctac fi neve
.tew meht teg ot spil sih skcil ekidpU
.kniht ot gniyrt hguoht sa drawpu skool ekidpU
?ytnewT ?setunim net
,yrots a si mih morf tnaw I lla taht swonk ekidpU
.kniht uoy yaw eht ni ton tub
”?regnad ni efil ruoy htiW
.sleeh s’enoemos no drah fo kniht nac uoy
,mlac si noisserpxe siH
.won thgir hcuot ym ot mraw si rozar s’maccO dna ,seil tuo ffins ot hguone tsaf dekrow gnol sah dnim yM
,won thgir derit eb dluohs I
,xiS emuloV raoR ni
.ylneve yas I ”,emit erom em ewo uoY“
.snekaew elims s’ekidpU
.ezilaer ot gniht gnibrutsid a si hcihw
tluciffid os neeb emit thgir eht ta ecalp thgir eht gnidnif sah reven tub
.nrael ot hcum os
.ffuts dab yllaer fo sdnik lla
.acilisaB eht ot tsew dedaeh t’nsah eH
.tcartnoc taht pu kcip ot eno ylno eht t’nsaw I nehw tub ,yrros m’I“
,emoR edistuo tsuj og ot secalp lufrednow emos era erehT“
.ycnetsisnoc htiw tuo dna ni evom sega dna ,sezis ,seiceps lla fo elpoeP
hguoht sa trihs sih no sgut neht dna
.feiler htiw hgis I ”?thgir
s’IBF eht otni gnikaerb llac uoY“
,yticanet ym dna gab aremac ym dna em
etuor tcerid a ekaT .setunim ytnewT
,aremac sih no sehctiws eht htiw selddif eH
.tnemom a tsuj rof nrut I dna
”?ercoidem srevres eruces
.mih ot revo klaw I ?won tahW
,emit eht ta taht wonk t’ndid I
”?gnihtyna naem taht seod yhW“
.erom gnihton dna fo elpmaxe na edam eb ot sdeen ohw ecnasiun a tsuj s’eh yas
.dnuora nrut ot egru eht tsiser I dna
”?uoy t’nod ,otohp a tuohtiw hguone llew eson siht rebmemer ll’uoy kniht I“
taorht etihw sih ssorca regnif dewalc tnulb a sward eH ”.dellik ,wonk uoy
.truoc nepo eht ssorca
”?dlrow eht fo naM“
eniw fo selttob htiw accetone ybraen eht fo tuo rednaw elpoeP .gnihtoN
,ecalp ni nezorf m’I tuB
,secalp fo stol ni sllik fo stoL
slanoisseforp …htiw peels I“
,daeha gnikool ,yaw eht sdael eH
gniticxe os t’nerew ti fI
.sriats eht pu evom ew sa
,yas I nac tahW  ?nos sih ti saw rO .rethguad s’nod aifaM a deoow neht
.htaerb fo tuo ylthgils si eh hguoht sa kciuq sllaf dna sesir tsehc siH
.pu dda ot demees ti ,emit eht ta dna
.gnitnarg s’eh lla si wodniw ruoh eno A .yddig m’I tub
”.uoy yonna ot naem t’nod I
.laer gnihtemos emoceb ti tel I tub
,krow taht lla rof evah ew did gnol woH
.rehtegot sgniht peek dna ti yalp nac I
.em morf ssorca gnittis s’eh taht ekil tsuJ
.redrocer eht sreggirt woble yM
.ecaf sih no gnisir tliug
,emahs dedda na tsuj saw redrocer ym gnikaT  …enog s’eh fI
.lla meht no seye peek t’nac
.niaga ecnartne eht no eye nA
,syas eh ”,mih tsap nar I“
.trap ecnedifnocrevo eht detcepxe fo dnik I
.ssalg sih sesiar dna noisserpxe ym sees eH  ”.ezoob fo stoL
”—dna ajnin gnidoc a gnieb rof kcab eht no flesym gnippalc
em tcetorp ot gniyrt em tem tsuj s’ohw enoemos dah reven ev’I dnA
,enilarp fo stnih htiw eugnot dna eson ym elkcit srovalf sseltnuoC
”.yenom ym detnuoc tsuj
,llah nwot s’aneiS fo rewot eht
.ekoj a s’ti hguoht sa snruter elims ehT
”.esohc naht rehtar detpoda uoy gnihtemos si ekidpU wonk I
.pleh eht deen ylerar hcihw ,sevren ym elttes dluow itnaihC fo ssalg A
.suorehcel yleniuneg eb ton thgim ro thgim taht elims a htiw drawrof snael eH
.raelc neeb reven dah ti dniheb gninosaer eht tub
”.meht fo tsom nettogrof ev’I“
ognoC eht ni noitpurroc gnisopxe morf yaw gnol a emoc ev’uoY
,riahc sih ni kcab snael ekidpU
?taht tuoba yrrow ot gniog er’uoY“
,dezingocer eb yllaer nac su fo rehtien dna
,gnivael em htiw yppah eb t’ndluow yehT“
.eson ym htiw hctiwt sreksihw yM
”.eb ot neppah I erehw thgir morf syawla m’I ,tsenoh etiuq eb oT“  .sgurhs ekidpU
.pot ssalg a htiw xob gnol eno ees dna flesym nrut I
.erehwesle su stiawa sraef eh tahw naht retteb s’ti sseug I tub ,pu seirots eerht erots ni dah eh tahw wonk t’nod I
,dnats ytiruces eht ot revo klaW“ “—s’tahW“
”?sruoy fo eson etuc taht tuo gnirb nac I fi neve toN“
.ronaemed lanoisseforp a rednu deirub ti peek I tub
,rotcaf a saw elcitra noitpurroc ognoC eht dna ,gnitroper ruoy rof ereh ma I  .on dna seY“
,lartuen erom gnihtemos otni gnilttes nirg sih
,emit gnol a rof sdef .S.U eht gnidave neeb dah ekidpU taht nwonk d’I
.gnol rof ti gniyalp eb lliw ew ekil ton s’tI
.mih retfa ozallaP eht ssorca gniyrruh dna gab ym gnibbarg
”?…em s’ti yhW“ .tibbar deirroW
,spord eciov sih yaw eht morf llet nac I ”.won thgir ti oD
woble ym tser ot ecalp a evah I os kcab nikpan eht hsup I
,od I tahw etaicerppa yllaer dluohs uoY
IBF eht retfA ,haeY“
.stnirps eh sa gnirettulf srae
.em llet dluohs eh esle tahw gnirugif si ekidpU
.si eh sa elbuort hcum sa ni ydobemos rof dratsab ymramS
.tropssap ym teg ot evah I“
,drocer no og t’nod esruoc fo ohw
.otni s’eh gnihtyreve dniheb snosaer eht si em esirprus seod tahW
.aidem dna sretsbom morf gninnur efil sih sdneps ohw ydobemos morf tcepxe dluohs I tsael eht s'ti ,yltsenoH
,dlrowrednu eht ni sreyalp nwonk sa desop
sgniht lufituaeb yltceridni ynam detaerc msicsaf esohw
yeht sa nailatI lufroloc ni rettahc sdik eninac dna ,etalugnu ,enisrU
,sretsnom laer emos htiw smoor ni neeb ev’I ;eurt s'tI
.nodnaba htiw yawa gnippans si
,ereht ni si tropssap ym tuB“
.erauqs eht ni sdworc eht ot gnitrad seye
,ynacsuT fo traeh eht ni ytic elttil tniauq a ni erauqs siht no ereh tuo lesaew elamef rehto yna ekil kool I
”,uoy ekil ydobemos rof doog eb dluow saremac kniht t’ndid I“ .em tsap neht
.sih fo oge taht s’ereht ,oslA
,sgniht dab ytterp gniod elihw nosrep doog a saw I flesym dlot I nehw kcab
”.dereffo yeht tahw sseug t’ndluow uoY .oot mehT
.sekoj gnikcarc si eh ereh dna ,sruoh ni derusaem si efil esohw ydobemos ot gniklat m’I
.eessenneT ni srial
”,yamsid ym ot hcuM“
.gniht elohw eht tuoba stbuod gnivah m’I ezilaer I
.hgual a gniniartser ,rettum I
”?tahw no ti tnepS !ti tnepS“
,edis ym ta si retiaw dnuohyerg ehT
.flesmih fo erac sekat eh ylsuoivbo dna
— ecnats sih nediw ot trap sgel sih yaw eht ,seye gniworran sih morf
,cilbup ni od ot stnaw eh tahw od t’nac eH
,wollof t’nod I“  .knilb I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sdeedsim sih rof yrros yltsenoh ro etirtnoC
.dloreH dnalgnE weN eht rof retroper ,recnepS ycnaN“
.ereh fo tuo teg ot evah I
”?reyolpme eht saw ohW“
,elttil a ffo em sessip devieced neeb ev’I hcum woh gnizilaer tub
.tibbar eht morf hgis a gniward tixe foor roolf reppu eht ta kool gnignol a
,lanruoj elohw a llif ot hguone staerht etipsed ,siht lla etipsed tub
.smitciv dednetni sih denraw neht dna stcartnoc redrum elpuoc a eruces ot enilno mih sa desop I
daeha dworc eht ni noitommoc a ees I
,retaw etnazzirf a redro dna éfac eht ta taes a evah I  2 fo 1 traP
”?bom eht morf yawa gninnur retfa did uoy tahw em llet uoy lliw ,od I fI“
.od t’ndid uoy sboj eht rof elpoep eseht lla morf elots uoy yenom ehT“
.ssecca niag ot sedoc eht dah yehT
.doow fo kcits etihw gnol a syal
”?uoy dnA“ .tnellecxE
.erom on yas I os ,secneirepxe ym tuoba gniklat emit etsaw ot tnaw t’nod I
.nottub worra eht htiw wohsedils a hguorht nacs I
.suomaf eb yam I hguoht nooS
.xaler flesym ekam dna hgis I
.desufnoc skool dna eniw sih spis ekidpU .ksa I
,esruoc fo neht dnA
.noitpircsed yna evah t’nod I
”.yug doog a m’I taht won
.dnuora teg ot sraC  .sletoH
.wap nedlog a fo acilper detfarc a otni tliub senob lapracatem fo tnemegnarra na ta skool ekidpU
,yrotskcab sih rehtegot eparcs ot sdib etarepsed ni
.ycnaN ,od I tahw fo esuaceb ereh m’I
,ti fo htuos tsuj syal ot srefer ekidpU muesum ehT
”?naem uoy od tahW“  .sterger wef a
”.nwod deit eb ton ot tol a em depleh s’tI“
.segaugnal elpitlum ni skoob rinevuos
— eurt ebyam llits trap tsal taht
.rehtegot llew siht og ot desoppus t’nera gnitairufni dna etuC
.won thgir diarfa ton m’I os
,tuoba gnillim elpoep
.smra ym dlof I ”.ekidpU ,wonk ydaerla uoY“
.der eht yrt dna ssalg nwo ym esiar I
”?tegrof dna reylf yadirF kcalB rieht kcah I diD
”?ti llac uoy tahw s’tahT“
-- em eus ,noitanigami detadtuo na tog ev’I haey — dlot eb hturt
eniw sih fo tsal eht sehsinif ekidpU
.tniop egatnav suoivbo ylno eht ot pu kool I
,yllaivoj syas ekidpU ”,etal m’I yrroS“
,ti dessecca taht PI rehto eht no hcraeser emos did I
.ffuts ym daer ev’uoY“ .em nesohc dah
.ylkciuq taht flesmih desiugsid evah t’nac ekidpU
”,nem yloh dna spohsib dna stnias fo scileR“
.lla retfa esohc I efil eht si sihT
-- rof emoc ev’I ohw ,ekidpU dnA
.ni knis sdrow sih sa thgil ylkcis gnihctac senob eht
daorba skrow ylerar yrev
.pu delaid oot m’I won thgiR
,niaga mih gniteem fo tcepsorp eht ta tsehc ym ni murht traeh ym leef I dna ,setunim ytnewt dias ekidpU
,floW pilS yb ”sdeR nacsuT dna ,stibbaR ,scileR“
,omouD lI fo dne kcab eht ot esir taht spets eht ot emoc I
.eniw eht spis eh sa yawa skool eH
,ereh pu tixe na s’erehT“
,dnuora nrut t’noD“
.erehwyreve era saremac eht erehw siht ekil ecalp a ni ro
,syalpsid eniw etanro rieht htiw spohs ssap I
”.noitanalpxe na uoy ewo I“
.sedecer elkraps ehT
,raen gnidnats er’ew seno eht sa laer sa senob dnif retal ot ylno sgniht fo sedis rieht gnitteg
”.em ta thgiartS .em ta kool
,rewot eht fo stohs era erehT
,uoy retfa tsrif saw tnemecrofne wal nehw kcaB“
.ydaerla t’nsi ti fi ,si tik ym erehw srekcol eseht fo eno ni eb yltrohs thgim ti
"?yenom eht htiw od uoy did tahw oS“
,emit htruof eht roF
.gniyas s’eh tahw ezilaer I sa secar dnim yM
.evank s’omouD eht ni muesuM“
sgniht dab od ot stcartnoc yub I
,emoR ni nwod noitats-sub eht ot setanidrooc detpyrcne eht
?tahW  ?cilbupeR ananaB“
.spotfoor eht ot seog
”.fo wonk I taht ofni nelots ym fo esu eno eht s’tahT
,snaicitilop tnatsiser-ebirb rof ekil erew sliated ytiruces eht tahw
”?ti si ,won em gniwollof er’yeht ekil ton s’ti sulP
.ereh ton er’ew nehw uoy llet ll’I“
”?uoy ot emag a lla ,siht si tahw oS“
.sniev ym ni gnis ot gnitrats eniw eht
,sotohp on evah dehsilbup ev’I selcitra eht lla no senilyb ehT
.yadyap ym tcelloc nac I os siht hsinif dna
.mih wohs ot tnaw t’nod I dna
.ssalg dniheb secilahc dna sexob etanro dedlig
,esnes sekam lla ti taht woN
”.dlrow ym ot emocleW“
mih ta ezag ym worran I ”.gniht doog a s’tahT .ecalp eht revo lla saremac era erehT
,draeh eb t’now drow yreve erehw
.elims a tsiser ot evah I flesym etipseD
”?thgir ,krow fo enil ruoy ni toN“
.ycnaN ,laer lla s'tI“
,redluohs ym revo levart seye siH
.ycnaN evitiguf elbisnopser a m’I esuaceb
,nwod kcab yaw ruo ekam eW
.srenid-oitap fo gnorht eht tsniaga tuo gnidnats ,elgna rediw
.rae ym skcilf thgir ym ot pans A
.thgiarts pu gnittis em steg tahT
,dnuora nrut I sa naorg I
.yawa pils ot uoy rof deneppah taht nehw hguone detcartsid saw eh yletanutroF
.sepirts latnoziroh ni elbram kcalb dna etihw
.daeh ym pota gnidnats ruf fo psiw eht ta gnikool tsomla
?detacilpmoc os eb ot evah siht did yhW
.nwod aremac sih tes dna
.tnasaelpnu gnihtemos diova ot gniyrt ydobemos fo gniraeb eht sah eH
.yllooc em sdrager lluks tac sselwaj a ,sbreh dna esnecni fo dnats a nO  .thgil kaew s’moor eht sehctac ,ecilahc lanogatco na ni ,meti txen ehT
,elgna hgih ylemertxe na morf si lanif ehT
.ereh ni yrd oot si ria ehT
.nikpan ym ot txen em fo tnorf ni nwod soruE era ereht eciton ot nwod gnikool ,raews I
”.ereht pu yaw ylno eht era sriats ehT
gnikcit dnah s’laidnus a ekil si rewot taerg eht fo wodahs ehT
.ecniw taht ekil t’nod yllaer I
,nwod em wols ot noitcudes erom eno sa
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
NFC htiw neztilB floW
,kcab tis I ”.nar dna
,od I tahw etah ohw rewop fo elpoep tpurroc yllacitilop htiw separcs dna noitadimitni
,ytiurf si ollenurB ehT
,em dlot sah gniggid ym tahw si sihT
.sdrawkcab gnikcilf srae ,ezeerf I
,tuo teg dna rof emoc ev’I tahw teg tsuj dluohs I
,detaefed s’eh nehw etuc fo dnik si tibbar ehT
,ma I ohw swonk ydoboN
,yadyap suoires a gninrae dnA
,”sdeR nacsuT dna ,stibbaR
.ega htiw tneb dna derruf-nworb si ereh tibbar ylno eht tub
.dekrap si rac ym erehw
.boj ruoy od ot gab ruoy fo stnetnoc eht deen t’nod uoy sseug I dnA
.nug eht rednu elpoep ot derettam taht ecnereffid a edam
.ecnedicnioc a s’taht ecnahc on s’erehT
.yaw ruo seye oN .gniog gnimoc
”.gab aremac ym teg ot evah I“
”.eromyna ti od t’ndluoc I“
,hsal kciuq a slaets liat ym dna ,nworf I
,dlrow eht htiw gnorw s’tahw htiw tcatnoc tcerid ni em tup syawla ot smees krow fo enil yM
.emaf citsilanruoj ot mialc a
.tellaw ruoy tsol ev’uoy meht llet dna
”.nikpan ruoy daeR .did I seY“
,tnempiuqe htiw srehto lareves era erehT
.htiw laed ot dah I seussi erew ereht tuB
.yldekoorc smaeb eH
.yadot ereh mih was I“
.flesym ta suoiruf oot gnitteg morf em spots nepo sesnes ym gnipeeK
.em weivretni ot dekcip I ohW“
.rewot eht nwod dna pu serutaef suoirav ot gnitniop elihw
,noisicedni s’tnemom a retfA
.ffo ti tes lliw gab aremac ym fo stnetnoc eht ezilaer dna yletaidemmi srotceted latem eht eciton I
.tcartnoc ruoy no ecnavda eht htiw thguob saw tahT
.rood eht ot neht dna moor eht dnuora trad seye s’ekidpU
,ti rof tnew dna stnelat ym htiw retteb gnihtemos od dluoc I dediced I
.lla retfa niav ni neeb t’ndah troffe taht llA
.yllacificeps ,daeh ruoy no eno ehT
.edirts ni egdelwonk eht ekat I
.secneuqesnoc erew ereht
”.oot uoy ot tnatropmi si
.yrrow ot trats I
…sreniater eht rof pu tes dah d’I stnuocca knab ot secnavda koot
.tibihxe eht gnivael erofeb noitcerid ym ni eralg a sworht esroh eht dna
.gnihcraes dna gnitfis fo shtnom retfa ,ereht thgir ,ereht mih dah I
.dnamed hgih ni flesym dnuof I ,boj
”?taht gniod peek ew od woh oS“
.suoicipsus taht dnif dna shtnom owt tsal eht rof mih ylno gnikees neeb ev’I taht ezilaer ll’eh fi rednow I
.em ot ti dnah ot dnuora ti snrut
,spihs latsyrc htiw dellif apparg teews fo selttob lacirehps
.uoy teem ot ti dekcip I snosaer eht fo eno s'ti
.lworg ot ton yrt I
,hguoht ,tibbar siht ylnO
eh yhw ot sa niatrec saw tub ,rednow did I
,setacidnys tsaoc-tsaE rehto dna kroY weN eht rof yltsom
”?uoy s’ti yhw tey derednow uoy evaH
.snedrah noisserpxe siH
”.siht fo emos yrt dluohs yllaer uoY
”?niaga saila ruoy degnahc uoy nehw taht sI
.ylwols tuo shtooms taht ssentrat ycips htiw etalap ym sehsaw dna ,prahs tey
.dellik saw ydobemos dna dediar saw yrtnuoc tsaE-raf a ni yssabme nA
,ralloc s’trihs-t nworb ym tsniaga dlog tsomla ruf ym
,erofeb regnad latrom ni neeb ev’I
.efil nwo ym rof raef yna fo tuo ton dna
.htaerb sih hctac ot gnisuap
”.ecno ta snoitazinagro esoht lla deyarteb uoy oS“
,emag sih si siht fI
.noitcaer a rof enim hcraes seye eulb siH
,srats nevig neeb evah ymotana ym fo strap ynaM
”.tol a taht spleh lohoclA
fo lluf moor a ni dnats ew
,eno gnorts a neeb dah mih retfa nur ot erised ehT
”,ecnegilid ruoy rof sknahT“
.og dna rekcol ym morf gab aremac ym teg ot evah I
.sesnel fo snezod yb derutpac eb lliw ,em ro
,em teg taht did erehw tuB“
.detceffasid dna mlac kool ot yrt dna sdnah ym dlof I
.tnew retiaw eht erehw ees ot pu skool dna
.enog si redrocer ym ezilaer I erofeb
”.yawyna detrats ti woh s’tahT“  .wols gnihcnum
,yllarutan os nirg sti sraew elzzum tahT
.rettib ylthgils dna yrw s’ti ,niaga elims sih sdnif ekidpU nehW ”.puY“ ”?meht etelpmoc t’ndid dna
,em ot tekcit-laem a si eh taht
,inilossuM fo sevitcerid eht no stcepsa laveidem sti ni devreserp ,ereh ytic lufituaeb a s’tI
.ekil s’taht tahw wonk uoY
.tnereffid elttil a eb ot desoppus saw sgniht fo edis lanimirc eht tub
.yaw ym snrut ti sa spans aremac ehT
.deppots uoy neht
,em hguorht gnikool seye eulb esoht leef nac I
.em ezingocer d’eh luftbuod s’ti tub
.nwod eciov ym peek I tub
?tahW“ ”.tellaw ym si sa
,rae tfel sih no sduts eulb owt dna trihs dnab seixirT a htiw derruf-etihw ,tibbar ehT
.won thgir su gnirednih ro gnipleh era su no saremac eseht lla fi rednow I
,htaerb peed a sekat ekidpU
,ksa taht skool edart dna sgab redluohs evitcepser ruo teg ew ,ytiruces ta tuO
,stcartnoc eht detpecca I
.suoiruc dna soiruc eht tsgnoma ni gnivom erofeb telbat a no eivom noitca na gnihctaw regdab dexaler a htiw eef ecnattimda eht elttes neht dna
.emal gnieb s’eh fi niatrecnu hguoht sa
,kcah yreve rof stcartnoc no gnikat detrats I ,enod tahT
”.tuo drow eht tup yeht ylerus tuB“
.t’nod esaelp ,oN“ ”.uoy llet em tel
”,naem I tahw wonk uoY“
.rumef s’lammam a s’tI
.elbat eht no swap sih ta skool eH
.ffo ti ekahs dna sreksihw ym no retaw fo pord a teg I
.sgel ym ssorc I
.erofeb eson etuc a evah I dlot neeb ev’I
,won hcuot ot hguone esolc s’eH
.esoht dedivorp I
”.ti tneps I .on …hu ,hO“
”.dereffo yeht boj yreve koot I esuaceb dam er’yeht ,oN
.hcamots ym ni tip gnisirprus a stup seye esoht ni truh eht
.rettam eht fo traeh eht ot teg ot emiT ”.em tsurt
.yb yaw eht no flesym decudortni I dna“
,yawyna em rof efil sih gniksir s’eh tey dnA
.feirg laer fo tol a desuac emit eht ta sreyolpme ym rof tog I noitamrofni ehT  ?huh
.RLSD siht tog tsuJ
.esolc teg uoy sa noos sa swodahs eht ot yawa knils ll’eH
,ekil kool dluow rekcah retupmoc yna enigami d’I tahw naht evitcartta erom hcum s’eH
”.dam er’yeht dna ,ffo nar uoy oS“
.flesym emalb ylno nac I
,ecnartne eht ta rekcol yap a dnif I
,ylregnig ti tresni
.evom gnihsinif obmoc eht dna
.raewrednu ekil sesaila degnahc I ,dias I ekiL“
”.gnihtyna yrt dluow nissassa on ecalp a s’tI
,eciov tnetsisni ym raeh dna elzzum denimreted ym ees ot tnaw t’nod ohw
,no tis I riahc oitap eht fo rab ecarb eht staeb liat yM
.tnemeticxe ym gniyarteb
.sgalf detsam-ed ekil srae
,sgurhs dna shgis tibbar ehT
.esolc tik ym deen I tub
,dednetni naht reduol elttil a ti yas I ”.timmaD“
.trap taht tegrof t’nac
”?I did ,ecalp siht gnieelf eb d’I wonk t’ndid I“ ”?--uoy dluow yhW
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
noitan tpurroc dna noitazinagro lanimirc yreve tup nac stnemtnioppasid elpuoc a dna ,haeY
.yad eht fo sniamer eht yawa
.kcab riahc sih gnihsup ekidpU dnif ot kcab nrut I
,mrala eht ffo-tes dluow redrocer ym fi taht ezilaer I
”.aedi on evah uoY“
.cillydi erom eb t’ndluoc sgniht erehw secalp ni neve
”?nees gnieb tuoba deirrow uoy t’nerA“
.straeH fo gniK eht
?srorret gnidner-luos rieht dna scilbupeR nrot-raw morf kaerb a evresed I t’noD
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.rewot eht morf em tohs d’eH
.boj ym ta doog os m’I snosaer eht fo eno si ycnednet siht tub
ekidpU dna ycnaN woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.pis rehtona sekat eh sa ti wohs ot dethgiled dna nuf gnivah s’eH .sdon eH
”.wef a neeb ev’ereht haeY“
”?od ot desoppus I ma lleh eht tahW“
?yawa aremac sih tup ot tibbar siht ksa I naC
.meht neewteb aremac eht hctulc ylsuoicsnoc-fles teef ym sa desaerc snaej
,lleh wA .od I kniht I“
,tnomerialC nujniS llac yeht etoyoc ehT“
”’.nam daed‘ em sllac azukaY ehT
”.taht tuoba em htiw yppah oot ton s’eh ,haeY
?thgir ,ffo dessip ylemertxe eb ot evah yehT
.der sih gnippis erofeb ti no gniwehc dna lio evilo ni ti gnippid ,sregnif sih ni kcits daerb a slriwt ekidpU .sevirra eniw ehT
.ecneconni s’dik eht yvne dna eson nwo sih ffo etalocohc tnim kcil retto na hctaw I
.yella thgir eht dnuof dna steerts niam eht ot tpek I .epoN“ .rettum I
”.niaga ti did tsuj I“
.niaga elims deifsitas-fles taht s’erehT  ”.ti fo tuo
.tenalPruF yb dehsilbup
.stluser stnaw reyolpme ym
,elcitra taht ni raey tsal ognoC eht ni noitpurroc desopxe uoy nehW
.em no pu daer s’eH ”?uoy t’nevah
,yteiroton eht lufrednow sa
.nees ev’I sgniht gniteiuqsid eht fo ynam htiw laed dluoc I woh wonk t’nod I
…em fo sotohp sah eh fI
dna tnemssarah fo llet elif ym ni seirots ehT
.ollenurB fo lufhtuom a no ekohc ylraen I
yliria gnitfird stnecs breh dna allerazzom ,airezzip a tsap gnidniW
?ereht tuo ozzalaP eht no uoy thguob I eniw tahT  .haeY“ “—naem uoY“
.teef ym neewteb dekcut llits si gab aremac ym erus ekam ot kcehc I
.ma I egde no woh gniyarteb
.rehpargotohp ym s’eh emussa yam tcatnoc ym ezilaer I dna
stops rettoh ni neeb ev’I
”.rehto eht retfa eno ,epoN“
.yrruh a ni ylneddus s’eh tub
.nwod tup taht retfa rehtegot flesym teg ot etunim a deen I“
?gnivom peek ot noitatropsnart sediseB“
.sdon tsuj eH  …taht retfA