.sreens nujniS  .gnicar si traeh ym edisnI .ylmlac rewsna I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?ereh fo tuo teg ew t’ndluohS“
.enola tibbar taht dah uoY“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.ti wonk uoy dna esahc eht evol uoY
.snmuloc ruoy htiw elpoep dab nwod gnikat
,nuf dna erutammi s’eH
,seye gniworran sih morf
.won thgir tnuoc ot sah noisiced sihT
.htaerb ym hctac ot tnemom a ekat I
.thgilnoom eht ni
.sriats eht ot elpuoc reirret dekcohs a tsap seirruh dna
.hctiwt sreksihw tew siH ”.yrroS .oN“
?ssenhsiloof ro suineg taht saW
.rof desu saw atad
.ylwollahs don I  ”.yawynA“
.boj siht rof dekcap ev’I lotsip evif-ytrof
.elitsnrut eht spael skcals dna trihs dekcehc krad a ni etoyoc derruf-nat A
”.egnahc a deen I
.tuo yaw sih llems t’now ylniatrec eH
.esimorp I ;uoy teem ll’I“
.gnidils ,roolf tew eht revo drawrof mih knay dna nug enihcambus s’flow dednuow eht fo lerrab kciht eht barg I sa thgilf-ro-thgif ni em evah sexelfer-terreF .sedirts gnol ekat I
.daeh sih no ecirp egral rehtar a sah
.ni mih erul ot detnaw uoY
.rehtegot sbir sih gnidloh wap eno
”,hctib a saw yug taht gnisoL“
.ylkciuq sessap aesuan fo evaw A
.hsiw ym ti ekam dna dias ekidpU tahw rebmemer I
,srettahs dna elzzum sih htiw sedilloc ti ,dne revo dnE
.noitcelloc eniw dna hctocs sih ta skool eH
.niaga yrrow taht s’erehT
,tnecs sih rehtag I
”.esu ot gniog saw I
,gnizeehw ,edis sih no sllor etoyoc ehT
.ffo liat sih etib ot gniog era
.gniog speek dna ,ti srettahs
.noisiced a ot emoc tsuj ev’I“
.efil sih ni reve emit tsrif eht rof ylbaborp ,ecno ylgnignol kcab gnikool
.nworht ydaerla ev’I elttob eniw eht si os tub ,ria eht ni si nug siH
.weiv otni ylissem pets toof etihw a ees I dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sporp nwerts-ylmodnar wef a ylno htiW
.flesmih htiw desaelp smees dna enot ym sdaer eH  ”?uoy sediseB“ .sksa eh ”?ynnuf s’tahW“
.krow siht fo kcis m’I
.sdnuos taht sa diputs
.esrow dnuos gnidnal dnoces dna ecnuob ehT
.ecnatsid eht otni yawa gnillaf sfoor eht revo
.em dnuora mra na stup
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
hctiwt liat ym dna taeb traeh ym leef I
.tey tuoba tuo dnuof t’nevah tsuj I esrow tol a did yeht
,yawa pets I sa elkcuhc yrd a htiw sevresbo ekidpU ”,em ykcuL
gab ym ,revoc dnif dna yella tseraen eht nwod
.mih ta kcarc ot gnitrats tnemom eht fo sserts eht ees nac I
.gnihtemos ro srepap emos laets dna ni kaerb ot gniog erew yeht em dlot yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.ereh delttes gnitteg saw I dab ooT“
,tsaf ereht teg ot evah I taht ezilaer I
.suoires teg I ,troffe htiW  .ti ekil I
,deb taht no gnittis tsuj m’I
.gnizeehw tub lla ,noitasrevnoc fo yaw yb syas eh
,ereh fo tsew sserdda na si
,dworc eht hguorht ffo s’eH
.rewsna relpmis on s’erehT
,”sdeR nacsuT dna ,stibbaR ,scileR“   yojne esaelP
,mrala ytiruces eht ffo gnittes gab
.yug a dellik ev’I
dna-sni fo ytnelp evah ot mees taht sriats fo thgilf a pu
,srae dna ecaf dereksihw nwo sih fo lwarcs nootrac a rednu ,ti nI
.siht ekil noitautis a ni leef ot em rof noitome ngierof a s’tI
.pots dna ,foor enitrevart eht rednu krad retaw
,kciht no dial si mrahc siH
”?em rof efil ruoy ksir uoy did yhW
,mih retfa trats t’nac eciohc yM .t’nac I
.yas yletarucca nac mih tuoba yrots yna tahw ro
,ta doog er’uoy tahw gniod elihw tliug leef ot gniht egnarts a s’tI
ohw ekidpU deman tibbar gnikcah retupmoc demrofer a nwod desahc ycnaN retroper lesaew dipertni ,emit tsaL
,ti rof tnew dna stnelat ym htiw doog gnihtemos od dluoc I denigami I
.enod era sgniht woh t’nsi tahT
.yug siht htiw yawa nur ot gniog yllautca m’I
nees ev’I tnemtrapa s’yug lacipytoerets tsom eht s’ti
.sgnittuc sih tcelloc ot emoc rerahs-porc mullebetna na ekil
”.yas ll’I“ ”.tnemngissa no
.gninekcis si hcnurc ehT
,adnarbetnoF eht ta evirra ot spets lareves dnecsed dna renroc a nrut I
.yas nac I lla si ”,seY“
,em secaf dna snrut eH
dnoces etanoissapsid dloc eno rof gninwad noitingocer
.yzood a saw eceip ognoC ehT“
”.suoires m’I .yug yracs a saw eH
,aremac sselhtrow yllautriv ym tsap
,yad eht ni etal sihT
.suomaf teg dluoc I os dlrow eht ni koorc dna def rehto yreve ekil tsuj uoy hctac
,revo dlrow eht stops thgit sseltnuoc ni denoh
.ereht ni gnihtyna deen ot gniog m’I kniht t’nod tsuj I
?siht lla morf yawa klaw yhW  ?yhW
.shtaerb wollahs sward eh sa
,wodniw tnemtrapa s’ekidpU fo ssalg etalp eht steem kcab s’nissassa eht dna ,setelpmoc thgiew s’flow eht fo refsnart eht sa deb sih no kcab sllaf ekidpU   .redluohs gnitiaw ,gnikcud ym revo nwod seog eh dna tnurg mih sekam ylleb eht ot tsif A
,niatnuof dessecer eht yb tnemom a ekat I
.og ot yaw gnol ,gnol a tog s’eh si eh sa nuf sa tub
.tsiaw ym ta gnilgnad
,edis ym ta gab aremac ym ,tsohg a sa tnelis ,sriats eht nwod daeh I .ssap stnemoM
”.mih ot em taeb uoY .pu emac I nehW
.tsal t’now tnemom ehT  .enola llits m’I
.srekcins eh ”,hturt eht wonk ot tnaw uoy fi detnuom dna ,deffuts
.ruf ym no ria looc eht dna
”.em evas ot yaw ruoy fo tuo tnew uoY“
,etorw uoy selcitra esoht lla detnalp uoy wonk ll’eH
.tpircs fo tros emos gninnur potpal a
.toof a htiw yawa gab aremac ym gnihsup ,hgual dna nirg I
,gnieelF  .lufrednow
,nur ot yrt dna tcartnoc ym rof yenom eht ekat d’eh thguoht I .seY“
.yawyella eht retne ot sa os thgir naht rehtar tfel gninrut
,lleh ekil struh tsrubtuo tsal tahT
,daeh ym ni thguoht a evah t’nod I dna
”.od uoy tahw od uoy elihw noitcetorp teG
”,won ,og ot evah eW“
.ti ot txen nepo stis stsurc azzip htiw reniatnoc tuoekat A
.der nacsuT ni flow tew ydaerla eht gnisuod
”?esuoh-efas rehtona evah uoY“
.retal rof yawa delif ecneserp ym
.senotselbboc s’yella eht ot nwod seirots eerht lla hguorht ria eht spir taht lwoh trohs a s’erehT
.stuhs rood eht sa raeh I tahw raeh t’nseod eH
,moor eno tsuj eb ot sraeppa ti
,seirots ruoy retfa nur uoy woh ekil s’tI
.guh kciuq a mih evig I nehw flesym ta desirprus neve ton wohemos m’I
.ti no pird t’now eh os tsuj ton s’tI
— ecnats sih nediw ot trap sgel sih yaw eht
”.ti evol uoy dna dekooh teg uoY
,htiw erolpmi ot sdrow txen eht rof sehcraes eH
.kced dexaw-etihw s’thcay a no dekan gnignuol nexiv a ot nepo
,no og t’nac eh swonk eh fi rednow I
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
noitanitsed txen eht ot daeh dna
”.gnihtemos no ti etirW .setunim ytnewt ni esuoh-efas rehto ym ta uoy teem dna seilppus emos barg ll’I“
.ssalc oduj ni noitneverp epar tuoba tol a denrael I“
.dnatsthgin eht no stser oy-oy deloopsnu nA
”.etisoppo eht etiuq ,oN .oN“
yrotimrod tsomla ,ynit a otni neht dna stuo-
.mih ot revo gnivom dna teef ym no m’I .erac t’nod I
”.llew retaw gnippird sedih taht pu yaw a koot I gniht dooG“
.mih htiw gniog er’uoY“
”,esiwrehto gnitteb m’I“
.ereh si nissassa eht
.giws a sekat eh sa ksed eht ot sllaf gam eidun gnidnats eht dna ,hctocs a skrocnu eH
”.ereht thgir rewohs a tog ev’I
.ycnaN ,ot deil saw I
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal
,deb eht no gam-ruf rehtona s’ereht ksed eht no ssem siht morf ssorca dna
.ereht aremac eht revo tuhs ti gnippiz
.uoy lliw oS .niaga nur ll’eH“
.ylatI fo tuo sthgilf xis thguob margorp ym ,yakO“ .mih llet I
kcar gnidaer desivorpmi na ekil enizagam tluda na pu gnidloh era hctocs decirp hgih fo selttob eerhT
.emit dnoces eht rof em morf yawa nettog gnivah ,yawa nissassa eht del sah ekidpU
?ti od uoy did yhW“
.meht fo htob fo tiusrup toh ni sevitarepmi nailatI stuohs draug ytiruces regdab ehT
”.dennalp dah I lla yllaretil s’tahT
,gnidnats s’eh erehw ot rood eht morf retaw fo liart elttil a s’erehT
tibbar eht teem ot
.egamad niarb fo tesno eht morf gnireffus s’nujniS fi ro ekoj yls a si kniw eht fi wonk t’nod I ”.snoitnetta
.t’nsi taht eno rehtona neht
.deb eht morf seye dliw htiw em ta gnirats ekidpU ,tnemom a rof llits htob era eW
.sdraobroolf looc eht no gninihs
.spil sih no doolb s’erehT  ”?…tahw
.deeps kcenkaerb ta llits sexelfer ym ,lortnoc rednu flesym teg ot evah I
.kcar eht ffo sehtolc yub ,pohs rinevuos a otni kcud I
.muesum lepahc omouD eht fo ksed ytiruces eht ot revo secap net gniyrruh
”.htiw evil ot evah reve dluohs
.acilisaB eht rednu niatnuof tsedlo s’aneiS
.ereht tfel ev’I sgniht elbasopsid regaem eht rof letoh ym ot nruter t’now I
,leetneg tub hguor si eciov s’etoyoc ehT
,pleh rof tuohs t’now eH
.sraey ynam os retfa
.denethgirf nehw elbaroda skool fo dnik eH .gnizidnargga-
,enizagam eht llup I sa yllud maelg ebut rosserppus dna emarf stI
”.thgir er’uoy sseug I“
.niaga og mih tel I dnA
enil yrev eht saw tahT“  ”!won thgir daed
”.gnivil a rof od yllaer uoy tahw nrael ll’eH
.eitfos a saw eh gniwonk tcartnoc eht koot uoy ,esaelP“
,elyts-nrut eht spoh
”?raf os gniod I ma woH“
,telbat sih no mlif noitca eht morf pu skool regdab ehT
”.yaw eht no gnikat er'ew seno hcihw ediced ll’I
,”sdeR nacsuT dna ,stibbaR ,scileR“
.rewsna t’nod I ”.I saw oS
”.thguac teg htob ll’uoy dnA
.nug eht rednu elpoep ot derettam taht ecnereffid a edam
.eniw der yb deneknip yllufemahs si ecaf nat siH
”?dah eh nug fo dnik tahw ees uoy diD
ettenehctik dna moorhtab eht naht rehtO
,revo gninrut m’I stbuod eht sretsiger ekidpU …sgniht rehto rof desu teg uoy ,yllautnevE  ’.elpoep dab‘
.gab ym ot nwod hcaer I
.hsiw ym rof snioc ekil enihs noitinumma fo sdaeh-reppoc ehT
.moc tod rettiwt fo yletal ,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.nwad eht ekil ecaf sih gnitrap nirg ,syas eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.yawa mih hsup I ”?tahW“
.flesym ta hgual tsomla dluoc I dna
”.nwo ym fo sgnorw emos xif
detivni ton si hcuot ehT
.regnad latrom ni peed siht elihw detraeh-thgil siht tlef ev’I emit tsrif eht s’tI
”sdeR nacsuT dna ,stibbaR ,scileR“
,eniw fo elttob nepo na si ti ot txeN
.smra sih ni em sekat dna wodniw nekorb eht tuo gnikool stsiser eH .evila leef I
.ekatsim sih s’taht dna ,nug eht esaeler t’nseod eH
.retupmoc sih ot em tsap spets
.deneppah tsuj tahw ssecorp ylurt dna
,shtped s’retaw eht otni ezag I sa dna
.eromyna rof emac I tahw tnaw t’nod I
.yas I ”,nujniS olleH“
,ni sevil eh tnemom hcae fo noitarepsed teews eht ekil sllems eH
,segnahc emos ekam dluoc I kniht I“
?sdef eht otni flesruoy nrut ton yhW“
”?yzarc enog uoy evaH“
.gnituohs morf peek ot hteet ym tirg I
.mih dnif ot enod ev’I lla gniredisnoc
.emit gnol yrev a ni
,ereh ydobon si ereht
.retal naht renoos
,neht dna tuo mih ward uoY
,enim teem ot ylfeirb nrut seye detnilf yerg siH
,stimil-ffo lla era aneiS ni sbmocatac eht ,haeY“
,rood tnorf eht tuo m’I
.ereht si nissassa ehT
.tenalPruF yb dehsilbup ,xiS emuloV raoR ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw
.etisbew rehtona hguorht elcyc ti sehctaw eH
.romuh fo esnes eht etiuq sah eh ynam morf draeh ev’I
.devlovni rednatsyb a teg t’now
.ybraen bruc eht ta pag s’niard rewes a nwod flesti nug eht pils dna esir I sa gnihcaorppa sreklaw thgin-etal fo gnirettum eht raeh I
.elknirw eson ym sees eH
.duol tuo gnihgual pleh t’nac I
”.laer gnihtemos emoceb eil eht tel ,esaelP“
dlrow eht ni dratsab live yreve ewo I .meht ewo I oS
”.xes evah dluoc eW“
.dlrow eht ni erehwyna
.spird eh dna ereht dnats ew sa stnemom wef a rof sessap ecneliS
,sserdda eht ot goj etunim net toh a s’tI
gnithgir s’eh dlrow eht ni sgnorw eht lla taht dna tuo gninnur si kcolc sih taht
”.neppah t’nseod tahT
…ti esu ot seitinutroppo fo tol a dah I
.sdnema gnikam trats ot emiT
.sliat rieht htob no toh si ohw nissassa etoyoc a morf regnad latrom ni won era dna
,em ta gnizag erofeb ti retfa skool flow eht dna yella eht nwod raf
.tellaw s’nug derih yreve ni ecaf ym ,yenom gib eht m’I“
.taht wonk ot daeh ym ni tuoyal s’aneiS fo hguone evah I
.stniop eh sa gnihsulb
.wodniw eht tuo skool dna ffo sliart eH
,roiretxe looc sih etipseD
.woleb sdray neetfif ydob s’etoyoc nekorb eht fo kniht t’nod I
aremac s’retroper a ylno gniraeb
.nissassa ’sih‘ ,noitcerroC
,moor eht morf seirruh eh sa mih ffo yticirtcele eht leef llits nac I  ”.esimorp
?tsoc tahw ta tuB
anneiS fo spart tsiruot dewollah eht hguorht esuom-tibbar dna tac-lesaew fo emag feirb a deyalp yehT
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     .thguac ev’I
,ecnelis otni snaorg eh dna
ekidpU sa noitseuq ni gnisir srae
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,drow a yas t’nod I tub
,mih no ytnuob eht rof ni mih ward ot flesruoy no tuo tih taht tup uoy revocsid ll’eH
.llot sti nekat dah emit tuB
?dedaeh tfos uoy erA …uoy t’ndid yhw
,ni knis sdrow sih fo thgiew eht tel I
.wodniw ot rood morf sdray eerht naht ssel
,rood eht dnuora sreep ekidpU
.sgniht dab enod ev’I ;uoy dlot I“
.seod eh tub hgual ot nujniS struh tI
.gniod s’ti tahw od ot enola enihcam eht evael I dna ,og dna emoc etisbew enilria na ees I
.redluohs ym ta ytiruces eht sees eh sa
.reve rixile suoicerp tsom eht si taht gnidiova fo noitaralihxe eht dna
,ylluferac snepo rood eht sa deppiznu gab aremac ym sah dnah yM
.esle gnihtemos dnA
.etoy‘ siht llik t’now I dnA
.mih dnuora dnuorg eht seolah doolB
.ssik a rof ni sevom eh sa pu og sworbeye ym dna
.yadot thgilf ruo dnoyeb lerdnuocs siht htiw gniyats ni detseretni neve m’I fi aedi on evah I
.oot ti leef I yhw nialpxe t’nac I
,spord eciov s’ekidpU yaw eht morf llet nac I  2 fo 2 traP
.etarebiled saw reffats taht fo gnillik eht dias swen ehT
,gniod sti revetahw gniod ,setisbew hguorht ylsselmia rednaw retupmoc sih gnihctaw
,gab eht morf dnah ym evomer I
”.yug taht dellik uoY“
”…deniatbo eb nac spam erehw wonk uoy fi tub
.ot deil saw I dna ,pleh ym htiw
eman ym ni ecifircas fo tca dnoces esohw tibbar eht fo nikpan eht nepo I
,ecitcarp lacinilc htiw sevren deyarf ym elttes I sa em tsniaga ecnuob edart ym fo sloot ehT
,renroc a dnuora yrruh I sa motnahp a wodahs yreve ,gnidnuop eslup
.yawa klaw ylerem
.steerts gnidniw s’aneiS ot sdrager ni raf os tey dna esolc os
retroper a seod sgnorw fo dnik tahW“
.ereh thgir esuoh-efas a sah eH
.elpoep gnorw eht retfa gniog m’I tub
.tib a sknits eh dna
,yademos tuo dnif ll’eH“
.deelb mih hctaw I
.ffo llup nac eh ylno yaw a ni niaga gums gnikool
”.did I thgir nmaD“
.edistuo gnikcud erofeb htiw daeh ym revoc I hcihw eidooh aneiS fo ytisrevinU a no tup dna moorhsaw cilbup a ni egnahc I
.snrut eldnah-rood eht nehw ,eno ton
,em hguorht slevart rettulf dloc A
.ti tuoba garb ot evil dna tcartnoc a no tuo klaw t’nod uoY“
,llirht taht evol I  .eromyna toN“
,won tsuj deid tsomla I
,omma tniop-wolloh eht pord dna ,epip eht raelc
.emoclewnu ton tub
.siht ekil gnillems ton ,lleW“
.ffo ekidpU sehsinif nissassa eht esac ni
ydobon sgniht od ot em ekil elpoep esu ot seirt ohw
”.dennalp uoy tahw t’nsaw ti yas t’noD
.srepsihw eh sa sredluohs ym dnuora swap sih ,ylegas sdon eH
eb dluoc ew ,ylsuoireS“
hcoK relkceH eht tuo llup dna
sleef yllautca ti dna
.seye ytliug ,yrgna esoht dniheb no gniog gnihtyreve wonk I .wollaws I
tnemtrapa eht ot rood ehT “—
,gniht fo dnik taht od ot eno ton m’I ;feirb s’tI
”.tnedor derae-gnol-a-fo-nos gnikcarc-edoc uoy ,lived eht teem ot emiT“
.tnemom yrev siht ta daed s’eh naem llew yrev dluoc
.ylevisnapxe shgis
,yawa nug sih kcik I
.eb dluow ti dias nikpan eht erehw ttam eht rednu yek a htiw tnemtrapa ekil-
,won redrocer dna
.ylniatrecnu srae sih syalps ekidpU  ”?nwo ruoy fo sgnorW“
.emit gnol a rof ,ti devol dah I
yrotS ralucitrap sihT
?em htiw gnorw si lleh eht tahW
.retaw ykrum eht otni ,tibbar gnieelf a nwod gnikat rof nesohc
.levon tsrif sih gnitide htiw no rehtruf tib elttil a tsuj won si dna
.spam esoht evah t’ndid dneirf eninac ruo dab ooT“
.niap htiw delddum noisufnoc
,uoy dnif ot ereh emac I ,ekidpU ,yltsenoH“
.noitnetta s’tnega eht rof retnuoc eht kconk I
.boj rehtona tsuj si sihT
”.secalp wef a rof egnarra syawla I“
,wonk I lla rof dnA
modnaF yrruF eht ni skrow nezod wef a dehsilbup sah ohw ,floW pilS yb
.boj a nevig erew uoY
,neeb reve s’ti naht niatrecnu erom si erutuf ehT
.nug gnikool evisserpmi na saw ti ,llew ,hO“
IBF taht tahw rof yrros gnieb tsuj naht erom tib a s’ti ,si gnihT
.ni dekcik s’ti sa srettahs tub lla
,tohs gnieb naht gnileurg ssel tol a si dehpargotohp ebyam dna deweivretni gnitteg ,lleW“
”.ereh fo htron tsuj s’noitats niarT“
.elihwa eb dluoc ti ,ereht nwod tsol s’eh fI
,tibbar siht gnidnatsrednu ot resolc on m’I leef I
,gab rethgil eht tfil I sa tnemom gnissap hcae fo snoitarbelec htiw em gninokceb efil wen elohw a
.nwod gnihsarc emoc lla ll’ti dna
.ti emit-elbuod I sa nworf I
.ycnaN ,gninnur s’eh elihw krow tseb sih seod tibbar eht esuaceB“
fles tey dna trams
senotselbboc dloc eht tsniaga gnilttes elzzum sih
.em dnuora nwod selttes ytniatrec a tub
”?taht od uoy did woH“
.ti gnituohs morf mih speek enilanerda tneps-ydaerla ylnO
.slaitnederc sserp esoht dekaf
gnisahc ta ma I sa doog sa gnieb ot secneuqesnoc era erehT
,gniht egnarts a si taht fo noitazilaer ehT
.shguoc eH  ”.yrroS .thgiR“ ”.tibbar ,tsaf ooT“
,ereh retupmoc a si erehT
.mih dniheb rood eht stuhs dna tnemtrapa nwo sih otni spils eh sa erutsiom yb dettam ruf sih
,tnemom a rof og stel eH
.hgis gnol a sevig eH
kcab stnilg gab ym fo pot no egdab sserp degrof-ylluferac ehT
”.uoy yaper neve nac I woh wonk t’nod I“ .elkcuhc I
.htaerb deniap a sekat nujniS
”…uoy tnaw yeht yhw wonk I taht yas I nehw tnemilpmoc a sa ti ekaT
…ym evresed t’nseod eno sihT
,wodniw eht tuo ezag I
?gniht nmad a naem taht dluohs yhW“ ”.mih ton
.pu em dessem yllaer evah dluoc ti teb I
tsrif mih dnuof uoy fi nehT“
,yalps srae siH ”!oN“
.tnemnorivne gnivil sih hpargotohp ot ecnahc a detsaw ev’I
,ydobemos deredrum yehT
,gab ym otni hcaer I
gnileef won m’I ekil ehca na tlef t’nevah I
,ti llac ot tahw wonk t’nod I
,daed eb yam retsam sti hguoht neve yalp ta ekidpU fo wodahs a
,em retfa ereh erew uoy skniht eH …tub
.woleb raf morf naorg eht raeh t’nseod eH