.yadhtrib yppah ,dias I
nemstfarc eht lla ,won tuB
.aisA tsaehtuoS morf retirw a ,gnuP .J .H yb
eno dezingocer flow ehs eht ,hgih pu morf nevE
.sare dna semit tnereffid ni
,ecamirg a htiw remocwen eht demrifnoC
,gnihton dna gnihtyrevE
,snoitacilbuP lluG yb noitaN a fo lobmyS
.enog saw niap taht lla dnA
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,rovref suoigiler fo retnec eht neve saw tI
,ezag tnatsnoc s'nus eht fo naf taerg a saw ehs hguohT
.gnimoclew yltcaxe t'nerew stnias eht dna ,daed gnol erew sdog namoR ehT
,elbram eht ni kcarc elbazis a ssorca arohpma reh rof gnihcaeR
sicnarF .tS dna rehpotsirhC .tS ylnO
?yawyna ,ot kaeps ehs dluow ohW
,htiw nial d'I ohw rebmemer t'nac I kniht ot ,ssendooG
,yad a ni tliub t'nsaw amoR taht gniyas a stsixe erehT
.flow gnuoy eht dias
,ti denigami dah yeht fi gnirednow ,dnuora dekool slatroM
.sraey flah a dna dnasuoht a revo
.spil reh dekcil apuL
.dog dna latrom serugif fo sessenekil elbram eht htiw gnola
,ssalg fo spohskrow rieht pu tes seitlaiceps lla fo nemstfarC
,dleh are siht fo slatrom eht
.ereh reh rof tfel gnihton s'ereht taht
.ecnart a ni ro peelsa ylgnimees rehtie
.elpoep reh fo taht hguorht tub
nettogroF eht gnirebmemeR saw sihT
sgnieb lanoitan taht tcaf eht rof ton ti erew
detsat syawla eniw eht ,rewop s'niamod reh fo thgieh eht tA
tluc a neve saw erehT
.stnemhsilpmocca ruoy ton tub
.elbram mraw eht tsniaga talf
.flow gnuoy eht demialcxe
?em htiw od ot tog taht lla sah tahw tub ,uoy rof dooG
.teksab a nihtiw desacne mottob sti
tcaf eht ot kcab del hcihW
,ecnelis elbatrofmocnu na otni tuo deid taht smaercs
.ailatI saw os rehtien
?woleb nwod riaf eht ees uoy diD
.ailatI detinu a saw hcus
,amoR fo taht tsuj ton
.eson sih erofeb ria eht gnivaw
ecnamrofrep klawedis a sa hcuS
,elzzum nwo reh fo noitcelfer a ta gnikool neeb evah dluoc ehS
.naem uoy ,gnieb pu dehsaw A
,pu dekcap rehtie gnivah
,ikahK yb uoy rof daeR .gnuP .J .H yb
,lla ti was ehs taht seye nwo reh hguorht ton saw ti dezilaer repuL ,neht saw tI
separg detnemref gnol fo ssenruos prahs ehT
.derever eb llits dluoc
.desaelp yeht reverehw tnew yehT
.seirtsudni egattoc yb decalper srekam arohpma dna ,srettop ,seirekab nees dah ehS
,sevil llits ycagel s'elpoep ruoy hcihw ni ytic a
.keew tsal erew yeht sa yadot snoisserpxe emas eht hcum
,gnihtyna deveihca evah ton llew sa thgim I
,dnik yna fo noitcelfer on detibihxe
.fo trap a erew elpoep reh stneve sseltnuoc eht yb deugalp peelS
,amoR fo gnidnuof eht etarbelec elpoep eht ,yad siht nO
.senob reh ni elgnit eht yb tub
.tlep keels sih ot sthgilhgih gnignirb
.sliated eht htiw flesreh rehtob ot deen eht ees t'ndid ehs tub
.yhw tuo derugif reven dah repuL hguoht
,elttob eht gnikrocnU
.raey a fo stnemges tub ,syad ro ,sruoh ,setunim ni ton detnuoc saw emit
.saw ehs ereh os dnA
,enog erew stnorferots rieht dna
,aM ,yadhtrib yppaH
,ainnellim owt revo rof dnuora saw eno nehW
.semoh rieht ni derepmihw sgod laref elihw
taem deruc dna ,eseehc
,nerdlihc dna nemow
,srovalf evitcnitsid fo sdairym deirrac ti ,esiw tnecS
,rehtona yb dleh elop a nopu tas yug emos hcihw ni
.nihtiw truh llud a saw gnissap hcae
.detsixe evah t'ndluow elpoep ym fo srehtaferof eht ,amoR fo elpoep tneicna eht fo ecnadiug ruoy tuohtiW
.ytic eht ot etsaw dial yeht sa
,lufhcaorper dekool remocwen ehT
.tcepxe ot tahw tuoba gnihton reh dlot ti ,yllausiV
.retnuocne eht fo ssenegnarts eht rof
.flesti tneserp dluow ytiddo rehtona
.senotselbboc ot yaw evig sbals gnivap nees dah ehS
.lobmys a rof dellac dah ailatI fo elpoep ehT
stserof sseltnuoc hguorht snoigel eht fo hcram sseldne ehT
,erefretni ot derac apuL fI
.derab sgnaf dna pu deffulf ruf
.feileb rieht morf htrof dehtrib saw tI
.ti timda ot erac t'nod yeht fi neve
,revewoh ,taht fo enon did remocwen ehT
,gnineppah s'tahw ees ot steerts eht lworp dluow apuL nehw emit a saw erehT
.emoclew syawla saw kcans doog a
.foor a no gnipeels ,gnol revewoh
.shtnom eseht ekil tlef ehs woh saw tahT  .neeb saH
,derats ylno apuL
,seye rebma htiw etelpmoc
.deworran seye s'apuL
.sedapacse ylhtrae s'retipuJ dethgilhgih taht
,lluf reve hguoht
,repooL dehgual ,reh dnuoF
,skriuq dna seitiddo nwo rieht dah are hcaE
.enog gnol era elpoep yM
.thgin ro noonretfa
?ton yeht erew ,nettogrof
.noitan a fo traeh eht saw ytic siht ,kcab seirutnec wef a ylno dnA
.doog nmad detsat eniw siht
.os ton tey dna ,railimaf os ,steerts esehT
sllah eseht degnorht slatrom sseltnuoc tuB
.eldi tis t'ndid flow eurt A
.pihsrow enipul ot detacided
.teerts a fo noitcerid eht ni gnitniop ,doots flow ehT
.mohtaf ot epoh t'ndluoc apuL snosaer rof
.ytic eht fo esnapxe eht ssorca sgnidliub dekcarc eht ta derutseg ehs
,gnihtyreve nees d'ehs thguoht ehs nehw dnA
.yreniw latrom tsenif eht ni taht sa detnemref llew sa ,teews dna ygnat
,enog erew elpoep reh hguohT
kcab sraey ynam os nellaf dah taht eripme na woh reh dezama tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.fo esiug eht koot yeht snamuh fo egami eht evas
.eid t'ndluoc sgnieb lanoitan ,tuB
tlef repuL netfo taht hcus
.elzzum reh htiw edis eht ot derutseg apooL
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m'I
.erom ecno delims flow regnuoy ehT
rof flesti detaeper dah taht smaerD
t'nsaw ti fi gnicnarp dna pu apuL evah dluow
,noehtnaP eht fo foor eht no degnuol apuL
.edutilos ni efil reh fo tser eht evil dna
.relur ralupopnu na ynam fo gnilppot ehT
tnemeticxe rof esuac yna yldraH
?ecalp koot eton fo sgniht erehw ereht t'nsaw ,lla retfa ,rof
.tuohs dna gnos yreve detsacdaorb taht
,snoitaripsa dna sepoh s'rebmem yreve dna hcae htiw gnola
,raef ton ,noitarbelec rof sllac ti thguoht evah dluow I
secnamrofreP
erew serutaef sdog eht fo hcum taht tuo detniop evah dluow ehs
erew uoy sa tsuJ
.nettogroF eht gnirebmemeR yojne esaelP
,seye sih ni deraeppa elkniwt a ereh ,tcaf nI
,daerb hserf fo ffihw eht thguac apooL
nettogroF eht gnirebmemeR
,arohpma reh fo stnetnoc eht tub ,erom ro htnom a rof xaler reh tel dna
.flesreh koohs flow ehs ehT
,swap reh dessorc flow ehT
,ecneserp reh ot gnimoclew erom eb ot demees
.seidegart dna seidemoc htob
.lla ti draeh dna nees dah eno nehw
.detlit elzzum sih
.ti hguorht degammur wap sih
,sedacaf elbram dna srallip eht ta dekwag dna emac stsiruoT
.swap sih tuo daerps eH
,erdam ,sruoy fo tluaf on hguorht saw tI  .dehtaerb ehs
,secalp ynam os ,secaf ynam oS
tneve dna lavitsef yreve nees ydaerla dah ehs rof ,tsap gnol saw emit taht tuB
,llef elpoep demeetse reh fo eripme eht neht tuB
,enod dah ti doog eht lla roF
,ytic eht fo steerts eht gniklaw ot regnarts on saw apuL
.goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil er'uoY
.ronoh reh ni pu tup slavitsef eht gniweiv ni kootrap neve dah apuL
,ytic eht fo retnec eht ni dnuopmoc dellaw taerg eht htiw
.noitseuq reh detaeper dna
si yrots s'yadot dna
,did slatrom ekil ecnanetsus deen t'ndid sgnieb lanoitaN
ecalp gnikat seitivitsef ehT
,flesti detneserp diuqil der fo elttob neerg a erofeb
,depmuj nipuL ,ecnetsixe reh gnirud emit dnoces eht rof dna
.tpels dna seye reh desolc ehS
,eulav tnemniatretne sti naht snoitnetni sreppihsrow reh ot tnemegdelwonkca na eroM
,ecneulfni ruoy morf detifeneb sniamod ynam
,erdam ,eniw dna doof siht ni ekatrap uoy tuoba woh oS
,reh raen ecneserp a tub
,pu sdliub yllaudarg
.tsehc yffulf ecno reh fo ruf dettam eht nwod gninnur stnuoma suoipoc ,taorht neht
.sdrawretfa meht tae ot tog ehs tsael ta tub
,tnemtneser ro raef tuohtiw ytic eht maor dluoc sevlow laref nehw emit a derebmemer apuL
.sgnieb lanoitan htiw erus reven saw enO
.arohpma reh fo taht naht ssel raf
,neeb ti dah gnol oS
,syalp namoR ralupop ynam gnirutaef
.ecioVehT ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.niamod dlo reh ni wen s'tahw tuo kcehc ot ylno fi
kootrap ehs gnihtemos eb ot desu tI
?htrib s'amoR fo yrasrevinna eht ton ti si ,sediseB
,dezingocer ehs taht srovalf
.semit fo elpuoc a sllaw sti nihtiw derednaw dah repuL
.kcarc a tsuj ,nepo seye reh
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,efil reh fo tser eht etsaw dluow apuL taht toN
.lautirips gnihtyreve fo emotipe
.reve sa gniltsub sa erew steerts gnidnuorrus sti dna erauqs ehT ~ gnuP .J .H yB
.ssel on staet nwo reh htiw elpoep eht fo srednuof yrev eht desiar d'ehs ,kniht oT
.noisulli lacitpo on saw eh taht gnimrifnoc
.siht ekil semit rof dah syawla ehs tahw did ehs os
,reh ekil tsuj ,flow a saw eH
.thguard peed a koot dna
guj eht deppotsnu flow ehs eht
.wap dekaerts eniw a htiw flesreh ta gnirutseg
.dekcilf srae s'remocwen ehT
.yrenif dna ,krowlatem
elpoep eht ot knil tsal s'repuL dnA
.htaerb tsal rieht werd elpoep reh ecnis saw ti gnol os rof
.sthguoht reh htiw enola eb t'ndluoc ehs
liat reh ,seye deddil flah htiw lla ti gniweiv
elpoep eht ot sdnob latnem lla reves ot dah apuL taht hcus
,tleb reh no nus eht fo ecnesba eht yb ton ,ti tlef ehS
.ecnetsixe s'elpoep reh fo seirutnec eht ot derapmoc rulb a sa deretsiger ti ylkciuq os deneppah taht segnahC
,reverof evil dluoc taht gnieb a roF
,wap tsrif meht fo elpuoc a nwonk dah ehS .detareggaxe
?yltcaxe uoy era ohW
,tnuoc dluoc ehs naht semit erom raf ti nwod deklaw dah ehS
,enadnum gnieb fo tniop eht ot evititeper saw ecnetsixe s'eno nehw tub
.ailatI fo setats ynam eht morf esoht sa wonk retal dluow tub
,timda ot dah ehS  .naidraug eno
.erutats ni rellams spahrep saw eh taht tpecxe
?tis tub gnihton did ohw enoemos ta yenom worht enoyna dluow yhW
.sserP lesaeW yb dehsilbup seirots rehto sah osla .J .H
,eniw fo stnanmer eht tuo raelc ot retteb eht
thgiew a ,elzzum reh ot pu ti thguorb ehs
,sey ,sgniht rehto gnomA  .apuL detats
.snoigel reh fo romra dna smra ehT
,deneppah evah t'ndluow ecnassianeR eht htiw emac taht egdelwonk eht
5 sroirraW floW ni sa llew sa
.mih dnuora wap sih gnivaw ,flow eht dias
.deksa apuL ?taht saw tahW
,elbisiv erew nwad fo seuh der eht ydaerlA
stnadnecsed sa nees erew yeht erehw
?yrtnuoc siht fo rednuof eht rof uoy ekatsim eno nac woH
,teksab a ffo htolc a gnitfiL
.esirprus ot deliaf reven slatrom nredom tub
.derehtob evah t'nthgim ehs
,apuL erit ot ylno thguos sthguoht esehT
snairabrab eht fo seirc elttab ehT    .stresed dna
.flow gnuoy eht dehgual
,eripmE namoR eht tuohtiW
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
.wap eno htiw elttob eht htrof dehsup flow gnuoy eht ,taht htiW
.elpoep reh fo duorp tlef ehs revenehw
doots ,elpoep reh fo eagilac dna sagot eht ni desserd ,srotcane eR
.emit s'apooL ni erar saw ffuts tahT  ?ssalG
.drah seye reh gniknilb ,dekool apuL
,gnikil reh rof secifircas lamina ynam ooT
.deddil flah seye
.dedavni dah yeht elpoep yrev eht yb dekcas ylkciuq
?srettam enod ev'I tahw kniht llits uoy dnA .tuo depiW
.lufniap saw egnahc
,etalucammi dna htooms saw ruf siH
,su ot meht morf dael taht sdaor ynam eht ekiL
.thgil gnineve gnidaf eht ni wolg tfos a ffo gnivig tsomla
.flesmih ediseb gnihcaer ,delims eh
yaw eht lla dennaps taht eripme na fo gnieb lanoitan a neeb gnivah ,ti dediova evah dluoc ehs taht ton
.deunitnoc remocwen eht os
.esle enoemos rof em nekatsim ev'uoy kniht I
,nus eht fo llaf dna esir eht htiw od ot gnihton dah taht elgnit larutannu na saw ereht tuB
.gnol oot raf rof nekops gnivah ton fo ecneuqesnoc a ,esraoc saw eciov reH
.saw ehs seitinivid eht fo
.snialp eht ssorca deirrac taht skrab fo otaccats hsrah A .dehgual apuL  ?htrib ruoY
,elihw a ni ecno teerts eht lworp ot deunitnoc ehS
,drah taorht reh dekcar ehS
.edis reh ot daeh reh dekcoc apuL
,niamod eno tub saw amoR erehW
.rovref s'elpoep rieht ro oge rieht fo tnuocca no degnahc yllanoisacco sezis riehT
.tneserp eht ot kcab apuL thguorb hcihW
.taht degnahc t'ndah sraey dnasuoht a fo trap retteb ehT
.sdnal reh ni elpoep egnarts fo gnilttes eht yb nekorb eb ot ylno
.yad eht yb esrow detsat won
ni dehsilbup saw yrots sihT
,noitcelfer eht dias
.tuo deid ro ,sedart dehctiws
,uoy nettogrof evah yam niamod ruoY
reh mlac ot desu egareveb eht ,ecnO
,seiranoigel dna nem fo smaercS
,enod d'I doog eht lla roF
ruovas ot gnihtemos ,noitaredom ni
,galf eno rednu llA
,yrtnuoc siht dettod taht skramdnal elbram dna enots eht ni deniamer ycagel sti fo hcum ,eruS
,tnemom eht ta no gniog rehto ro lavitsef emos rof snoitaraperp erew ereht wenk ehS
.gniweks reksihw sih
.nwod kcab tas apuL  ,nos ruoY
.etaneS eht fo llaf eht htiw deid dah
.dah ecno ehs sa elpoep eht gnoma klaw ot
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioVehT
.amoR fo elpoep eht yb
.eruliaf a reve s'gnieb on taht rebmemer dna
.sllah dewollah eht hguorht klaw a koot ehs revenehw reh nopu denworf syawla semit tnecer erom fo stnias eht ,tnesba erew dlo fo sdog namoR eht hguohT
.nettogrof gnol semit tuoba gnicsinimer ,flow dlo pu dehsaw A
.sehcaer nretsae eht ot
,eugnot reh ssorca tsrif gnuts
,rehto eht htiw teksab ehT
.erehwesle gnikool ffo retteb er'uoY
.ytic eht dnuora lla
,ylimaf hcae fo sliated eht wonk ot tog eno nehW
.tnemnethgilne s'elpoep eht ot esir gnivig
taht ygrene na deirrac osla srae thgirpu dna seye thgirb siH
,ksud ro nwad s'ti rehtehw wonk ot seye reh nepo ot deen t'ndid apuL
snoitpartnoc duol revo yb srae eht no gninefaed edam
.sniamer euqitsym eht tey
,gninoitseuq ni rae na derewol ylerem reh erofeb flow gnuoy ehT
.etercnoc dna camrat ot senotselbboC
,ymmum naitpygE na gnilbmeser eno yb decalper eb thgim noirutnec a sa desserd rotcaneer A