ot naahlaC dna ,nradoB ,sdoG eht naht rehto ,nosrep ylno eht erew yeht ,drawrof kcab deppets nahoZ sA .ysaenu dna desufnoc won ,elpoep fo gnorht eht otni kcab deppets nradoB .meht fo enon oT .meht fo lla oT
”,emahs elbaresim A
.elihw a rof gnuh ecnelis ehT
.ti raeh ot tnaw t’ndid eh wenk eh ,yas ot dah dniw eht revetahW
,eno yb eno dna ecnelis raen ni stcepser rieht diap noitagergnoc eht fo tser eht elihw ,sselhtaerb ,evarg eht yb tlenk nradoB .enog saw naahlaC
eot ot pitrae morf derevoc dna
.drow a ton ekops eh
.eugrom eht fo tuo raj cimarec egral eht leehw ot
.dluoc eh tseb sa gnorts dna tsafdaets deniamer eh
.gniliaf tub ,edis sih ot dna llits swap sih peek ot gniyrt ,sehcneb eht fo eno no nwod gnittis ,dias nradoB
.won thgir ton ylniatreC
”,evah I snoitseuq eht era esehT“ ”.snoissergsnart
.dnatsrednu mih evah dna em truh d’eh taht mih llet reven dluoc I
,yllanummoc enod saw trid eht gnidda fo tca ehT
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,flesmih rof tub teiuq won ,emoh ylimaf eht edisnI
.gniraelc elgnuj a ni detacol ,dimaryp gnilwarps a saw elpmet ehT
,eye prahs eht serahs nos siH“
.kaeps ot mih gnitivni ,nradoB sdrawot
naahlaC deveiler dna
eht dna ,niaga nahoZ tem yeht ,edistuO
.repmet s’rehtaf ym did os ,esrow werg niap eht sA“
”.deklat ew nehw kcaB“ .dias regdab eht
”,tegrof I dluoc woH“
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  lufraF lacsaP yb
.segap yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”.emahs eht eldnah t’ndluoc I dna
,euqinu eb lliw ynitsed siH
.yaced dna llaf neht
”.yaw siht si ti taht emahs a
.deen fo emit sih ni rehtaf eht ediseb saw nos ehT
”?em truh eh nac …swonk eh fi dnA
.siht ekil emit a ta ot refed ot esle enoemos evah d’eh yllamroN
.hguorht rettulf meht tel ot gnisuap xof eht
.tsehc rieht ot daeh sih gnidiug
.ecalkcen edaj eht tuo dellup dna xob llams a otni dehcaer nradoB
.sgob esned dna seert kciht htiw edis eno tub lla no dednuorrus saw tI
.deliaf evah lliw ew
.niaga seye sih otni ylpeed gnikool ,redluohs s’regdab eht no wap rieht tup yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ecnelis suomrone eht hcaorb oT .gnihtemos yas ot neek os ,os ,neek mees dna nradoB nopu kool dluow ynaM
eb ot em detnaw eH“ .denialpxe eh
…neht ,eurt si yas uoy tahw fi tuB“
.ysaenu dna detniojsid elttil a saw siht neve tuB
.raj eht revo tsac saw trid fo lufdnah tsal eht ,noziroh eht hcuot ot nwod tes noom eht sa ,gnitubirtnoc sgniw dna ,swap ,sdnah lla htiW .elpoep rieht fo eno gniyrub lla erew yeht ytinummoc a sa rof ,etapicitrap dluow delbmessa lla tub
eht ro sgob eht fo dum elbatrofmoc ,kciht eht ekilnu ,pu delip eb ot elba
.rehto hcae delbmeser yeht hcum woH
,rehtaf sih ot tnereffid
mih gnillet otni em devieced eh ,yllautnevE .ssorc ylbirret
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ylimaf eht yb del
thgisdnih htiw taht wonk ew
.ssarg eht fo pot eht rednu owt ro toof a ylno yal cimarec ehT
,evol evig sdoG ehT“
”.s’rehtaf ruoy ron
”.eerf elpoep tes ylno nac hturt ehT“
.kaeps ot dniw eht wolla ot gnisuaP
”.dluoc uoy tahw did uoY“
gnipleh ,edistuo erutluv eht del nradoB
”.did eh llew laeh dnA
”?eyE-eerhT fo elbarap eht daer reve uoy evaH“
.elpmet eht tuoba decalp setteutats llams ni dna
.mih tpurretni ot derad dniw eht neve toN
.tirips s’rehtaf sih ni deidobme si taht noitanimreted gninnuc eht dna ,ytisoiruc etutsa eht
”.tcerroc si raef sih swonk eh woN
,sdnah deppuc rieht ni pu ti gnitfil ,retaw revir eht otni dehcaer nahoZ
,shturt taerg lla fo eurt s’taht tuB“
,regdab eht ta delims dna denrut xof ehT
,gniklat fo elbapacni os erew ew ,dessap eh emit eht yb tub ,dnik ni sgniht enod dah I taht eveileb tsum I“
.meht htiw nwod gnittis nradoB ,raj eht sdrawot kcab dekool nahoZ
ot kcab seye sih gnirb ot elba ,denialpxe eh ”,dam mih evord tI
.laeh ot dluoc yeht tahw did stsinatob eht elihw snoitatnacni eht demrofrep I“
.enola nradoB dna nahoZ gnivael
dedaf elims siht tub
.ksa ot etilop oot raf lla erew yeht tub
.no gniog saw tahw dnatsrednu ylreporp
.deunitnoc nahoZ ,teiuq saw dniw eht nehW
.detnaw eh tahw mih evig t’ndluoc
”.pihsnik ruoy fo llefeb tahw dna ,yrujni sih ekil
.sraey rof kaeps dluoc eh ,sgnileef nekorb fo sdrahs tnatluser eht nO
.deraperp t’ndah eh taht hcum os t’nsaw tI
.oot srae sih esolc ot deirT
.nellaf dah thgiN
”.gniveirg morf tser uoy yaM“ - ”.t’ndid I“
denrut dworc eht dna
-  .etis lairub eht sdrawot dna
detnaw eh tahw mih evig syawla t’ndluoc I
.tnerappa saw trofmocsid s’nradoB sa
,flow dna retto na ,mih fo edis hcae ot esohT
,nwot eht ot kcab deriter ohw ,erutluv eht deknaht regdab ehT
.deffins nradoB ”,oN“
”?ti t’nsi ,rehtaf ruoy tuoba s’tI“
,noitcefrep eveihca nac sdoG eht neve toN .rehtaf ruoy dna
.niur ni yal won tahW
.dias eh ”,enod si tI“
.modsiw enivid eht ,snoitca eht ,sdrow eht meht dnah thgim sdoG eht morf gnihtemos taht gnipoh
.hturt eht kaeps erad ton did eh roF
”meiuqeR“   yojne esaelP
.sretsiger lacov nwo rieht tius ot
.erehda ot neek naht ssel spahrep saw I dnA
.nos dna rehtaf fo dnob laiceps tahT
.snrettap gnilzzad fo seires a ni eniltuo rieht pu gnikaerb
”…ton si taht ,dereves si evol ruoy erehw tniop eht ot rehtaf ruoy dna uoy htob edivid hcihw snoissergsnart
.gnimochtrof saw enoN
”?siht ekil dne ot evah ti did yhW“
.yrt ot ssengnilliw ruoy ,stpmetta ruoy
.teef sih ot tog dna deddon nradoB
”.shtnom gnimoc eht ni snoitseuq fo tol a rewsna ot evah ot gniog m’I kniht I“
.tsal ta ekops regdab eht ,enola erew nahoZ dna nradoB nehW
.ylluftsiw dehgis xof ehT
.htaerb peed a koot neht ,tesnus eht dna aes eht ot tuo dekool yehT .deddon nahoZ
…uoy neewteb ti evreserp ot ton tif was sdoG eht fi dna ,dnal eht ni ecrof lufrewop tsom eht si evoL
.oot mih egduj lliw sdoG eht neht
.deltsur seerT .deltsub segdeH
,ecarbme na otni nradoB gnisae ,deddon nahoZ
.yticapac cilbup a ni no tog yeht llew woH
:lliw taht fo trap tnacifingis tsom eht ot ylralucitrap dna
fo ydegart A .taht tsuj si ti
.thgilnoom eht ot pu ,ecalkcen eht tuo dleh nradoB .htaerb peed A
t’ndluoc …I dna rehtaf yM“
.elpmet eht otni deppets
.derettum eh ”,niap eht rebmemer tsuj I“
,ylteiuq yal raj ehT
”.ecaep fo ecalp a nI
,elbbub ,esir regna gnittel dna mrif flesmih gnidloh
.deredisnoc dna desuap xof ehT
.ti ni gnignir seciov eht raeh dluoc eH
wenk rehtom ym dna flesym edistuo elpoep weF“
.htaerb gnol a koot regdab ehT
.pu kcab doots neht
.sih ni swap s’nradoB fo eno gnikat dna tuo gnihcaer ,deddon nahoZ
,remmus ht42 sih tsdima regdab a ,nradoB ”.ni emoC“
.ytinummoc eht rof reterpretni lautirips dna redael suoigiler a
,ssol eht rof ton
”,eb ot saw I tahw ediced
,siht rof saw ti dnA
”meiuqeR“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
,mih trofmoc ot troffe na ni regdab eht fo dloh eltneg koot
.etis evarg eht dnuora decalp erew sehcrot tiL
deid eh nehw wonk I dnA
.yltnatcepxe mih ta dekool dna delffuhs elpoeP
dna dilos ylriaf deniamer ti tub ,ti hguorht poocs ot swap s’regdab eht rof ysae saw tI
”.erus rof s’taht ,ti raeh ot tnaw t’now elpoeP“
,nageb nradoB ”,snoitseuq evah I“
.trohs sevlesmeht deppots tub
.gnipleh nahoZ htiw ,raj eht yal dluow eh erehw dnuorg eht otni gid ot nageb eH  .denialpxe nradoB
tsap htob ,stnemhsilpmocca sih rof nradoB fo duorp naahlaC ees llahs ew
,secifircas ruoy rof htob uoy egduj lliw yeht tub ,sih rof dna ,seruliaf ruoy rof uoy egduj yam sdoG ehT“ .derettum yeht
.gnisaeler neht ,gnihctac taorht sih
hctip ni esor eceip eht sa ni denioj elpoeP
”.daed eht fo stirips eht tuobA“
,thgir t’nsaw gnihtemos taht dnatsrednu ot demees won elpoeP
.mih gnitceffa saw niap eht woh fo
.noitaroced ydob fo esu lufruoloc ,thgirb eht dna gnicnad dna cisum desisahpme elor rieht fo hcuM
.larenuf eht ta hceeps gnitraped a ekam ot ylimaf eht morf enoemos roF
,hturt eht meht lleT“
,revir eht sdrawot ffo derats nradoB ”.enola
.retaw eht ot dnuora gnippets dna pu gnidnats ,deddon xof ehT
,niaga welb sdniw ehT
.eurt saw ti deraef eh nehW
,enivid dna nommoc erew smrotsniaR
.eciov eht enigami ot toN
,em fo snoitatcepxe hgih
,llib reh detlit dna deddon drib eht tub ,erutluv eht delzzup tnemmoc tsal ehT
.tsal ta dias nahoZ
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.talf eil ot ti gnirvueonam
.emahs a si tI .drow thgir eht ton si tluaf tub ,gnorw si tluaF“
.ylpmis os reve ,derettu dna dehgis nradoB ,tsal tA
”.sdoG eht fo nedrag eht nI
,elitref ylbanosaer ,llafniar eht morf teW .lios tfos saw ereh niarret ehT
,sdrawno ti yrrac dworc eht tel ot gnignis deppots nahoZ sa ,dna ,gnos eht htiw ni denioj regdab ehT
.derepsihw regdab eht
,etanutrofnu era snoitautis emoS
”?tluaf ruoy saw htaed sih leef uoy oD“
”,elpmis taht ton s’tI“
ni moor eht dnuora lla deunitnoc erew sfitom esehT
.wap sih ni ecalkcen eht tpek tub ,kcab xob eht tup eH
.tser ot nwod tas nahoZ ,evarg eht otni derewol raj eht htiW  ”.nis a ton tuB
yrgna worg dluow eh dna
.dlrow eht fo sdliw eht morf detcetorp eb ot ,esolc
nradoB ”.yleerf kaepS“ .yltfos dias nahoZ ”,esaelP“
dah eh tuB .ti netaerht eh did ton ,tneloiv reven saw eH
.tsal ta ezag tfos s’xof deoottat eht gniteem ,nahoZ
.naahlaC oT .sessam gnidnetta eht oT
.tnedicca eht ot roirp tsuj ti detfarc d’eH .sey
.emoh dellac yeht egalliv eht sdrawot gnirats ,niaga derednaw ezag s’nradoB ”.snomed eht bmun ot sbreh hguone dah ew nehw mih was ylno did taht esoht dna ,mih was weF
.evarg eht ot klaw dluoc nradoB taht hcus detrap elpoep fo gnorht ehT
.emoh rof kcab detraped
.daeh sih koohs nradoB
,enim ron ,sruoy ton ,lliw ’sdoG eht si ti
.deunitnoc xof eht
,ylbadnatsrednu ,si siht taht feirg htiw derebmucne-revo os si ylimaf gnivivrus eht ,semitemoS
htolcniol a ni dalc xof a
”?rebmemer uoy od ,ecalkcen edaj taht uoy evag eH
.detnurg regdab ehT
.sdrow sti ot netsil ot ton deirt regdab ehT
.oot stcepser rieht yap ot derehtag dah thgin eht fo serutaerc eht fi sa ,delriws thgin fo kcalb ykni ehT
.nruter ni dewob regdab eht dna
.egalliv eht sdrawot kcab klaw ot nageb riap eht ,straeh yvaeh htiW
.deksa repeek-eugrom eht
.gnirutnevda ,gnirolpxe
”?deirub eb ot era yeht erehw dediced uoy evaH“
,yawa ti ekat nac yeht
”.secifircas rieht dna stnemeveihca rieht was osla eyE-eerhT taht si
,eruliaf taht rof lufetah dna yrgna si rehtaf ruoy fI
?edisni leef I tahw wonk ,htaed ni ,rehtaf ym lliW“
.sruoy ni uoy htiw eh saw sA
,revaewmaerD a erew yehT
.noitseuq eht dehcaorb nahoZ ,ecnelis eht nI
meht htiw edistuo nradoB detivni nahoZ os ,raelc saw yks eht dna thgirb saw ti won roF
”,ot tnaw uoy leef uoy fi
,raf elbignatni eht ,ecnatsid eht otni derats yehT
- .peew ot gninnigeb dna
ruo rof esigolopa ot elba eb reve d’ew kniht t’nod I
.nis a ton si tahT“
.ynomerec eht nageb nahoZ sa
.reyarp tnelis sih saw ”.pots ti ekam tsuj ,esaelP“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.erew I dna rehtaf ym woh fo dna flesym fo ylno wonk I .htaed dna efil dnatsrednu ot dneterp t’nod I“
,raj eht fo kcen eht dnuora ecalkcen eht desae nradoB ,eciov rieht derewol xof eht nehW
,egalliv eht hguorht raj eht htiw yaw rieht edam eerht
”,gnuoy saw I nehw tis ot desu ew erehw s’tI
.mih devol I taht gniyas deppots I yaw eht yb os detceffa saw eH“
.cisum taorht fo eceip lufnruom ,wols a gnis ot nageb revaewmaerD eht ,sgnideecorp eht edulcnoc oT
.revir eht dna ti neewteb doots nahoZ elihw
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.gnithgif ehT .gnituohs ehT
.deilper regdab eht
.gnillortnoc yrev saw dna
,revaewmaerD esiw eht dnuora smra sih gnipparw erofeb ,xof eht ta pu ylteiuq gnikool ,deddon nradoB ”.worros ruoy morf ecaep uoy hsiw I“
.won toN .ereh toN
,evarg eht ot ti gnignirb neht
”.smaerd tsedliw ruo dnoyeb srewop evah yeht dna
.eye eht ni nahoZ gnikool ,tsal ta dias nradoB
.detalfed nradoB ”?eromyna mih evol ot elba gnieb ton rof em rof etah evah eh lliW“
,sroolf nepo ,egral ot yaw evag dimaryp eht pu spets ehT
.raj eht revo ylwols ti gniruop
.tuhs seye sih dewercs nradoB
.etagergnoc ot nageb ylwols srenruom rehto sa ,etis lairub eht ot klaw eht nageb eH
.niaga seye s’nradoB otni gnikool ,hgis peed a koot yehT
.eyE-eerhT fo elpmet eht ta yltpurba desuap nahoZ
.gnorw saw tahw wonk ot dednamed eh ,relaeh a ees ot tnew I nehW
.erutcurts eht fo retemaid eht dnuora
.rehtaf sih dna nradoB htiw secneirepxe rieht fo enO .llet ot yrots a dah hcae tuB .tsom ta ytnewt ebyam ,dworc llams a saw tI
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”meiuqeR“ saw sihT     ”?ti t’nsi
.ylesolc ylralucitrap toN“
.raj eht ta derats nradoB .etis lairub eht ot detropsnart eb dluoc ti taht hcus ,tellap a nopu erac htiw dedaol
htron eht ot sgob yloh yddum eht ssorca
.taht retfa ni saw eh niap ehT“
.mih derussa nahoZ ”,si reve gnihtoN“
.niaga ekops dna kcab tas eh ,derit emaceb smra s’nradoB nehW .tliub saw nwot eht hcihw otno dnuorg drah ,gnorts
.seye s’xof eht otni pu yltpurba derats nradoB ”.mih devol uoy dna ,uoy devol rehtaf ruoy tuB“
,sniamer s’rehtaf sih deniatnoc taht raj eht ta gnikool ,deilper nradoB ”,uoy knahT“
”,yaw taht trapa llef ti taht tnemtnioppasid taerg a si tI“
,trid eht otni nwod ti gnisae ylwols ,raj eht tfil ot devom riap ehT
.dedeen nradoB ecnadiug fo dnik eht rof ton ,gnitarbelec dna ,gnicnad ,gnignis rof laedi erew tub
,kcab doots nahoZ ,dedulcnoc s’revaewmaerD eht htiW ”.erutuf ni dna
.meht htiw tis ot drawrof regdab eht derutseg dna deddon nahoZ
?eromyna mih evol t’nod I taht ees eh lliW
eman ni nos dna rehtaf erew ew
.raj eht revo trid eht gniyal ni
nettogrof si tahw tuB
.yks eht ot kcab neht ,tnemom a rof regdab eht ta gnikool ,dias xof eht
uoy htob fo eurt si siht dna
”?egami tcefrep eno ni tneserp eht dna tsap eht gniees fo elbapaC
.yas ot gnihton dah eh ,naahlaC nO
”.seinomerec ta meht fo dias ev’uoy tahw ylnO
.noisiv taht tuo ees ot dluoc eh tahw did dna ylimaf sih rof tseb eht detnaw ohw nam a was yeht ,naahlaC was yeht nehW“ .nageb yeht
.yas ot tahw aedi on dah nradoB .elbissop ton
,hguot emaceb semit nehW
”,won sdoG eht fo smra eht ni si naahlaC“
,kool laerehte na xof eht gnivig ,tniap ydob etacirtni htiw denroda ylhserf neeb dah yehT
?sdoG eht yb eye driht a fo tfig eht nevig saw ohw flow ehT“ .deksa yeht
,gninrael ,selgnuj eht ni tuo ,srehto eht ekil eb ot detnaw I
,lliw ’sdoG eht fo noitarbelec eht ot detoved erew yehT
redluohs rieht ot daeh sih gnisserp
- ”.melborp eht ylesicerp s’tahT .oN“
”,nradoB ,nos sih yb devivrus si naahlaC“
,kaeps ot mih gnitiawa dnuora esoht htiw ,doots eh sA
.teiuq saw ereht ,tnemom a roF .secalp rieht koot elpoeP
”,yawa edih dluow I dna
.mih eraperp dluoc gnihton taht eroM
.seruliaf rieht dna sekatsim rieht ees dluoc yeht ,tsap eht was eyE-eerhT nehW“
.eye eht ni nahoZ kool ot gnilggurts llits ,deddon
,nahoZ tas ertnec eht nI
.emoceb ecno evah thgim tahW .saw ecno tahW
.lortnoc ruoy dnoyeb si …tI .evol eht fo gnimmid eht rof egduj ton lliw yehT
.tsal ta eerf niap dna yppah naahlaC enigami tsum eW .niap sih fo
.nahoZ oT .sdoG eht oT
,thgiserof enivid dna
…tub esoprup no ton ylbaborp ,em truh dluow taht sgniht od d’eH
.dnalmraf sa lufesu eb ot revir eht ot esolc oot tub
.edaf ti tel osla nac yeht tub
”?yrgna eb llits eh lliw tuB“
,ebircsed uoy tahw tuB“
”.daets sih ni tnuh I nehw mih rebmemer nac I os em ot ti evag eh tnedicca eht retfa tub ,tnuh eht no ti raew ot gniog saw eH
”?erans eht htiw tnedicca eht dah rehtaF nehw rebmemer uoY“
,leef uoy erus m’I sa ,ylpmis si tI
.oot ereht erew uoy tuB“
tcefrep eb ot sdoG eht yb detcepxe ton era eW“
,riafnu saw erudne ecifircas siht gnikam taht was sdoG eht ,dne eht nI
ertnec eht morf spets erom detuorps neht
.emahs a ,ytip a ,tnemtnioppasid a si tI
.peew ot nageb regdab eht taht
.repmet sih dna lortnoc sih tneser ot werg I ,thguof ew dna yrgna erom werg eh sa dnA
,sgniward ,krowtra eht
.soottat dna tniapydob etacirtni ni
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.yrrac ot enola sih saw ,erutuf dna tneserp ,tsap ;nik sih fo thgiew ehT .eromyna os toN
.redluohs s’regdab eht revo mra na gnittup ,deilper xof eht
.deddon nahoZ ”.spahreP“
.kaeps ot noitidart saw tI
,ti revoc ot ydaer trid
.neeb evah dluoc I spahrep sa etaredisnoc dna dnik sa ,lufpleh sa t’nsaw I
”.yportne dna noissergsnart lautum
,ecalkcen ehT“ .deddon nradoB
.naahlaC fo taht naht yloh ssel on tub
.rehtaf sih ekil tsuJ .dloc saw enots ehT
.evorg eht ot devom neeb dah raj eht ,ruoh na nihtiW
.koorb eht yb evorg eht nI“ .deddon nradoB
.ria gnineve eht hguorht detfaw dniw eht fo repsihw ehT
.deilper nahoZ ”,si tI“
.eceip eht sselb ot noitatnacni na ekops nahoZ dna ,gnidnatsrednu ni derrits dworc ehT
.teef sih ot tog dna dehgis regdab ehT
,rehpargotohp dna naicisum ,retirw a si lacsaP .”ygolohtnA cirotsiherP A :gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW“ ni sraeppa hcihw
.woleb raj eht nopu nwod thgil taht detcelfer tI
.gnihton saw ereht tuB
.elbadnatsrednu …si ytisrevda hcus fo ecaf eht ni traeh ruoy ni evol fo kcal a tub dnif oT“
.seye eerht gniraeb ,eninac a fo eutats a saw meht dniheb sllaw eht nO .evoL
.ti fo tsom eht ekam ot
os werg eh ,yhw mih llet ot tnaw t’ndid I nehW
,sdneirf ni dna ylimaf ni ,semitemos taht rebmemer ot tnatropmi si ti suhT“
.ecnelis ni tas nradoB dna nahoZ
.tes neeb dah part a erehw seert eht otni gnikool ,tser ot emac ezag gnirednaw s’nradoB ,yllaniF
,detseuqer dah naahlaC hcihw taht hctam ton lliw
…tsuj I .mih truh ot ro ,mih regna ot tnaw t’ndid I“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.noitcerid tuohtiw dias saw tI ”.yrros m’I“
.yks eht otni tsac yromem A
.noitagergnoc eht ssorca ,seert eht fo tuo dehsur dniW
”.oot syaw taerg ni dedeeccus evah lliw ew ,semitemos tuB
”,raj eht rof stnemnroda eht tcelloc dluohs eW“
,sdoG eht yb dediced sa ,nradoB fo ynitsed eht hguohtlA
xof eht dia ot niaga htrof deppets
syawklaw lanretxe gnicudorp suht ,rehgih bmilc ot
.daeh eht fo ekahs mrif a ,deremmats regdab eht ”…I ,oN“
”.gniveirg morf eveirper evah uoy yaM“ .derepsihw yeht