mraw eil I lliw thginoT
.peed sa tsuj si tliuq ym tub
.noos si tI .gnisir si tI
.tfos yrev si deb ym dna yraew yrev era seye yM
evoba dna ,gnillews era pu lanrutcon stnecs terceS
gniltsur seert llaT
.enog ydaerla ma I
,gnitterf sehtolc esolC
.erom wollip ym evol I
.yawa raf si peels dnA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I .goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
sllih railimaf no gnidniw syaw gnortS
yvaeh ym no gnicarb ezeerb ksirB
:der netlom fo eniw a sa
.noom tnangerp eht dnuora gnilioc sduolc dloC
,floWcaM boR yb nettirw meop a gnidaer m’I yadoT dna
.gnuoy dna wen era sedalb eht
gninraey sdray gnoL
.niks gnirevihs ym ssorca srettiks htaerb tnacS
,nepeed shtped ksuD
.rehtie fo deen on evah I
evoba noom eht evol I sa hcuM
.em ot gnillac si thgiN
gniraelc sduolc dloC
.no slias noom eht sa
,thgin diulf eht ssorca
sllihc erif eht nehW
.doG fo ecaf eht ees yam ew ylkrad swodahsnoom ni erehW
,tfo gnitseuq enog evah I sniatnuom eht nopu tuo
.reh htiw klaw a ekat dna
:ruf ym pu selffur dna
.gninthgil yb kcurts neeb ecno yllautca sah ohw
kniht ot llirht I thgin yreve erehW
:ti gniod ydaerla ma I
.enog si thgil eht retfa gnolruf a semoceb moor A
.dloc diuqil a tuo gnitaews ssarg teewS
rood eht kcolnu I sa
.nihtiw yrovas dna
kaerts revlis eht mees sehsa ehT
.aes eht ot nwod dael taht sliar revlis yssalg eht sgnir tI
,dnah ym nihtiw lla era ssilb dna ,ssenluftegrof ,ecaeP
gnicarb si dniw thgindim ehT
hguohT .dloh lliw lliw ym tub
,yvaeh yrev si enot stI
.sedaf eltsihw eht ,enog si niart ehT
eltsihw gnirednaw a stfird nehW
.derevocsid eb ot llits llA
.od tsum I tahw wonk I
.em ot duolc enigne morf sesurohc dna ,sllac ,seirrac tI
.oot ti draeh evah lliw ehS
rorrim a ekil sllor noom ehT
.evol I reh fo ecaf eht fo
.erom on nruter yam I
,seot ym neewteb tfos si drawS .eugnot gnignah
,thginot edistuo og ll’I kniht I
,dnas detfis remmus sa neve sa stis ecneliS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,dlohserht nepo eht sthgil tI
yldliw sekaw dniW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
nialp nepo eht ssorca
.thgil yrev si eciov sti
.rood eht rabnu ron lliw ,thginot edistuo og ton lliw I
dort ew shtap tsedliw eht fo srepsihw dniw dliW
.peels fo laes terces eht htaeneb
.noom eht ffo deohce osla tahT yadretsey fo sgnos eht htiw sezinomrah dna slwoh tI
em dnuora teews llems sevael ehT
.niamer etihw dna kcalb dna enog si eulb dna enog si neerg nehW
.deb ni ydaerla ma I
:no sraew thgin eht sa
floWcaM boR yb moep a ,”sseL tseR“ :yojne esaelP