,arreiS yb uoy rof daer
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,.la te Æ yb ”ecneciter“ saw sihT
.taoc hcnert a ni snogard lareves fo desopmoc teop a ,.la te Æ yb
.enO eulB llamS eht
,kcits a htiw
,ees uoy doog nwo ruoy rof s'ti tub noitasrevnoc fo seorht eht ni degagnesid tsuj i wonk i
,relevart wollef ruoy floWcaM boR si sihT
enO eulB llamS eht ,arreiS yb daeR
.em edisni snogard owt s'ereht
ecneitap ruoy hguorht nrub ot yppah eb thgim owt eseht tnemugra eht otni kcab em kcirt ot gniyrt pots
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,”ecneciter“yojne esaelP
ecneuqesnoc eht htiw evil tsum i tub
.la te Æ yb meop a
meht gnikop pots esaelp os daeh ruoy ffo gnippans morf sretsnom eseht gnipeek m’i daetsni ,uoy gnirongi m'i ekil smees ti fi os ,repiv gnittips-dica na ,reh tem reven ev'uoy ,yhw wonk t'nod i ,uoy setah rehto eht thgif ot sevol eno
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY