.meht ecitcarp reh gnivah dna—lortnoc llab
dnim s’abeS ni yllanigram deretsiger tI
:kcab dehsur ,doolf a ni eno
,tey ABF eht ni t’nsaw eh taht denialpxe dna dehgual abeS
yponac eht yawa deruocs dah tnempoleveD
.gnirraj saw—emankcin tnecer a hcus htiw yllaicepse—emaf sih fo dednimer eb ot dna
,evaw a dna elims a htiw noisnet eht esufed ot deirt abeS
.egamirglip a fo wodahs a saw ti tub ,sedecreM
.cilbup eht fo noitnetta eht epacse ton dluoc eh
,wenk abeS ,litnu ytisned dna ezis ni dehsinimid hcihw
.gnir latem eht otni llab eht detcerid hguorht-wollof trepxe siH
,tfig a sa yesrej odarodlE bulC a dna
,tooferab tneps neeb dah efil gnuoy sih fo hcum ,tcaf nI
.etatse laer eht naht erom meht tuoba derac eh dna
.suolaej abeS elttil tfel evah dluow
.noitnetta lanoitanretni deniatta nos lacol a revenehw msaisuhtne lareneg eht dellacer evah dluow eh
.teksab retfa teksab dessim ehs elihw
abeS sdnimer ssendrawkwa reH
,draobkcab netaeb a
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,erom tnemom a noitautis eht gnihgieW
.denialpxe eh ,llikdaor neeb dah adnocana ehT
”.ffo skcos ruoy dekconk ti ,saw ti revetahw ekil skooL“
esroH eht odeloT yb
dezilaer dna yks eht ni nus eht fo ecalp eht deciton abeS ,taht htiW
)dekcol ,syawla sa ,etag(
”.sgniht wef a uoy wohs dluoc I ebyaM !ti teg dna emoc
.sniar remmus gnirud steerts yllih eht ni nar taht
,elims tub pleh ton dluoc eH
,elbat éfac eht ta nwod tas eH
detcepsus dah eh ylsuoicsnocbuS
,tnaillirb eht delaever dna—niks delacs sti—
hcuot ekil gnihtemos tuB
,elop kcalb a doots etercnoc eht fo dne rehtie nO
did eh tahw od dluoc yeht taht
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.fles regnuoy sih ot etubirt gnittif a eb dluow
?llabteksab yalp ot seohs deen eh did yhw
”,suocsuoC“ sa ti deredner yltnecer dah recnuonna nA
.elbuort ni mih teg dluoc
,wenk yeht lla rof
,edis rehto eht no ssarg eht ni gnidnaL
,thguoht retal eh
,ecalp siht ni ,ereh tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.revo ti dessot dna llab s’retsgnuoy eht ot revo deklaw abeS
nus remmus yb denedrah erew lios eht dna ssarg ehT
.llaw eht fo pot eht ot decnalg eh
.dedolpxe dah saw eh ohw wenk ohw sregnarts fo rebmun eht
.tooferab deyalp srellab wollef fo ytnelP
ecnef latem kcalb llat a dniheb
,srab s’ecnef hcruhc eht hguorht
,dna pot eht revo llab sih dessot abeS
”.spooh elpuoc a toohs ,secalp elpuoc a tisiV
,ecnis reve os thguoht dah abeS
.rehtona ro tros emos fo snoitcesretni ta tliub erew
,noisses gnihcaet utpmorpmi eht tuohguorht tuB
,ti deveihca tub egde eht revo flesmih tfil ot deniarts reed eht
,ecaf reh ni elbigel saw kcohs ehT   .dednopser eh
.ecnef eht revo flesmih dellup dna pu dehcaer
.21 atuR yb detcesib noitcesdim worran sti dna
.eurt eb ot tuo denrut etisoppo eht tub
,sub eht ffo tog eh nehW
.kaeb deuh-wobniar sih ssorca
.truoc eht fo egde eht ta tlah a ot emoc dna yb ssap llab a was ,gninrut
odarodlE ni ereh truoc taht no seohs llabteksab sih evael oT
.snolat kcalb dna selacs eulb was eh erehw
,denediw seye esoht dna dnoces rehtonA .revo gnirebmalc
”gninruteR“:yojne esaelP
.eno rehtona evaH .ereH“
truoc llams eht ta gnireep retfA
rehtaew senoisiM eht ot desopxe gnihtyna fo citsiretcarahc sedacaf deniats-erhco-der eht erob
,emoh doohdlihc sih saw erehT
,dekcarc fo esnapxe na tas
.dehgis abeS   ”.yppah kool uoy ,lleW“
;yromem s’eno ni ti fo hcum oot saw ereht taht saw
,sten neeb reven dah erehT
.ereht ylimaf dah regnol on eh ecnis yllaicepse
llabteksab nrowrevo ,dezisrevo na htiw dlo-raey-net eht tub
.ereh truoc llabteksab eht dnuof ehs dna
,pam a revo tneb htob yeht elihw
,erehwesle devil ylimaf siH
.seohs fo riap a rof inotreB adinevA ot nruter ot mih rof emit on dah ynnaD dna eh taht dezilaer ylkciuq sa tsuj tub
dna ,draobkcab no llab
.abeS deciton gnivah
tnediser remrof suomaf tsom s’ytic eht ylbaborp—
.adnocana tnaig a fo noteleks eht evoba morf delbmeser odarodlE fo ytic ehT
.woleb nwal eht otno gnippord yltfed dna gninnips
.taeh noonretfa eht ni spooh gnitoohs
.ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.sraey thgie ni emit tsrif eht rof niaga ereh saw eh dnA   .llabteksab dna
.dlrow sih fo trap a regnol on saw ti ,sediseB
.teerts eht nwod tol ytpme eht ni lobtúf rof tnew tsuj sreep sih fo tsoM
sub eht dedraob eH
,tnemesumeb emos htiw derebmemer eh
,reh troper ot ereht ton saw eh taht reh gnirussaer retfA
,elgnuj eht otni sretemolik 51 gnihsinav liat sti
,neiB“ .ediw llits seye
,yromem wen a nehw llab yawanur eht eveirter ot revo nur ot tuoba saw eh
,elims a htiw reh dlot eh
,dias ehs ,etneciV naS morf ereh devom yltnecer dah ylimaf reH .kcub a ton
:tuo ti tel ehs ,revewoh ,tohs a gnikam ni reh ediug ot reh ediseb nwod tlenk eh nehW
”?llab ruoy si taht ,oS“ ,gniksa
:snoitcesretni sih erew
.eramthgin sih syawla saw sgniht evisnepxe gnicalpeR
,pooh eht fo tnorf ni ecalp sih koot eh
”!gniyalp peek tsuJ
ot retteb eb dluow ti rehtehw ediced ot gniyrt ylsuoivbo ,ezorf nwaf ehT
.ecalp eht fo pam a was tsrif eh
,debburcsnu tfel dna
.drawpu tohs ehs ,teksab eht rednu thgir flesreh gninoitisoP
,od ot dediced yeht revetahw taht
.oksoiK ti deredner dah sruf desufnoc
.tuo dekrow ton llabteksab dah loohcs lacidem ot og ot deraperp dah flesmih eh
.noisivelet eht no neeb dah—
.kcab gnimoc t’nerew yeht dna ,tsol erew yehT
tnatsni na ni yawa detlem sgnap esoht tuB
.inotreB adinevA gnihcaorppa erew yeht
nacuot enitnegrA na wollof yltsom stiolpxe yraretil yrruf esohw
.truoc yrev siht no llabteksab gniyalp nugeb dah eh taht dna
etalocohc a desahcrup eh elihW
.drawpu llab eht dessot dna ,demia
,shtnom tsap eht revo detalumucca dah taht ytirbelec fo esnes lla yawa dehsaw dah truoc eht no eirever etavirp siH
,dedda eh ,dnA .detnaw yeht fi
,sllird fo sraey yb denut selcsum dna syalp htiw deffuts niarb
.etercnoc detnit-tsur
.htuoy sih fo yad yreve teef sih deroloc taht tnit emas eht
,tlah a ot ecnuob ot ti rof gnitiaw ton
,dna boj tniap wen a dah renroc eht no oksoik ehT
,palf elgnis a dna mra degniw eno htiw ,dna drawrof tpael abeS
.sub eht fo kcab eht morf dednecsed dna pots a langis ot nottub eht desserp abeS
”!poo-yella na taht llac yehT“
,thgis htiw elbuort ehT
!truoc s’hcruhc eht ta kcab seohs sih nettogrof dah eh
…ereh morf saw eh taht dna
.ffo skcos ym kconk did ti esoppus I“
,tnemom a rof detrats eH
”.sub taht hctac s’tel ,woN .doog roF
.dnuober eht mih evag secap elpuoc A
,tnemevap no llab fo dnuos elatllet eht raeh llits dluoc eh
.draug-ffo abeS thguac noitseuq ehT
,gnidnats dna llab nwo sih pu gnikciP
,saciremA eht dna eporuE
.detcartsid saw eh thguoht ehs nehw ylno tub
emag eht fo slatnemadnuf eht reh ot gnitartsnomed nageb abeS
etunim a flah rof dehctaw tub
,meht ekil tsuj saw eh taht
tfarD noitaicossA llabteksaB yrruF 4102 eht rof gniralced ecnis tub
.tnemegdelwonkca ni devaw eh ,woN
,seohs sih decalnu dna drawrof tneb eh ,nwod gnittiS
,teef nwo sih drawot thgis fo enil s’ynnaD dewollof eh litnu desufnoc saw abeS
,daeh sih revo eidooh odalA elprup sih gnillup etipsed taht saw—
.llab sih htiw emit siht
,dlihc llat a neeb dah eH
:emanrus hsiloP a fo syoj eht ,hA
,denrael retal abeS ,seitic llA
”?on ,suocsuoC era uoY“
”,taht em llac yeht esoppus I ,seY“
,agoriuQ oicaroH fo seirots eht no ydaeh
,ylegnarts abeS ta kool ot deunitnoc zuL
,etercnoc eht fo taeh eht morf gnignirc tsrif tA
.ynapmoc rof doom eht ni etiuq t’nsaw eh tub
,eod elttil a saw ehs dnuof—zuL—
.ytreporp s’hcruhc eht fo sretrauq-eerht degnir taht llaw kcirb eht tub
.deworrob dah eh llab a htiw ereh nwod emoc dah eh semit tsrif esoht fo
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
keew suoiverp eht egnellahC enibmoC tfarD eht dehctaw dah meht fo ynaM
,niaga steksab gnitoohs ot tes yletaidemmi dna deyojrevo demees zuL
,lla retfa ;taerg saw ti
dnuos elbakatsimnu eht draeh eh mih dniheb nehT
,yteixna hguorht gnikrow
,ecnef eht morf emoc ton dah tI
—ycrem evah doG— ro nájuL ro ítatI on saw tI
tnemevap dna sesuoh ehT
.mih nihtiw pu llew ot nageb tliug fo sgnileeF
,ohw enoemos fo weiv lluf ni llaw eht gnilacs hsinif ot ro
.nisuoc sih ta dehgual eh ”,haeY“
.won did eh tahw saw taht dnA
,nwotnwod éfac a ta ynnaD nisuoc sih gnivaeL   .hcruhc a ot saw ti
.ecnatpecca dna ,noitaneila
.og ot ecalp erom eno dah eH
ylper eht htiw dna eman sih deksa abeS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,dexifsnart erew yeht ecneserp sih nI
”?won ABF eht ni gniyalp eb uoy t’ndluohS
.hcruhc eht fo llaw eht yb skcos sih dna meht gnivael
.ereh sruf rehto fo lufdnah a htiw deyalp reve ylno dah abeS
,etadidnac tfard ABF eht ekil leef ton did abeS won roF
teerts eht nwod yawflaH
?ereh gniod uoy era tahW
.tuo dnats ot thgis a rof drah saw ti
wenk eh taht taef a—
.semitemos llabteksab osla dna ,hO
.pooh eht otni ti egnulp dna
.ecnerefmucric sti dnuora dehcaer ylerab taht smra htiw llab reh gnigguh
llab eht debbarg
.no seohs htiw truoc siht no deyalp reven dah eh
serutcip elpuoc a retfA
,esroH eht odeloT ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb ”gninruteR“
.snoitome dna sdoom llacer ot laitnetop eht dah
seye gniyrp eht morf yawa denrut ylpmis eh
.nekops eman sih draeh eh nehw semit elpuoc a erew erehT
,elttil htiw pu worg uoy nehW
.ecnef eht revo flesmih detfil dna niaga eybdoog dias abeS
lios deroloc-doolb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,flesmih ot delkcuhc abeS
,gniog saw ti erehw gnieeS
,dnoces a naht erom rof detcelfer eh daH
.egral era selims nacuot dna
,srewop lacitsym on dah eh taht meht erussaer ot tseb sih did abeS dna
sregnarts neewteb noitcaretni ot ti detubirtta eh tub ,siht gniod saw ehs taht
ecno dneirf a ot denialpxe dah eh ,adnocana ehT
,odarodlE bulC ta dellorne eh erofeb sraey eht nI
,democlew neeb evah thgim ni gnippots
.ssenffits laicos nevorp nwo sih dna
.elbativeni noitacifitnedi edam ylno mra sih rednu degdew won llabteksab ehT
,taes sih morf gnisiR
,flesmih htiw knarf eh erew dnA
reed gnuoy a fo ecaf deye-egral eht delaever regnol dnoces A
bulc citelhta lacol eht yb deppots dah eh ,sadasoP morf edir sub ylrae na retfA
.railimaf ylpeed saw ti tub ,teef sih tsniaga dehctarcs dna
dnah devooh elttil a was eh dehctaw eh sa ,hguone yleruS
.sretroper deit-eugnot gnoma tih tnatsni na
,yllacinori ,nettirw yrrow
nwaf elttil eht ot lleweraf edab eH
.niaga ynnaD htiw pu teem d’eh erehw ot kcab yaw eht lla delims dna
ti gnidnah dna depacse ti erofeb llab eht gnihctans
srehto yb deipucco ylsuoivbo won
.meht nrow dah reven eh dlihc a sa ,eromrehtruF
,mih gnizingocer sregnarts ot demotsucca nworg dah eh reerac egelloc sih revO
.tegrof t’nod uoy
.loohcs ta esu rof naelc devreserp seohs ylno sih
.reisae tib a etiuq taht edam llat sretem owt gnieB
.ereht setelhta gnuoy ylthgirps eht teem ot
.yb ssap yrenecs eht dehctaw dna
.suocsuoC derreferp eh dediced eh—
:mih no denwad thguoht a nehw
.kcab gnidaeh eb dluohs eh
”gninruteR“ saw sihT
,esroH eht odeloT yb
.úzaugI otreuP rof gnineve taht hctac ot sub a dah ynnaD dna eH
,reviR ánaraP eht ni deppid daeh sti dah
.revir eht drawot ,tsew sretemolik mih koot taht sub a dedraob abeS
.mir sselpooh hguorht llab—eciwt ro ecno—
”!evorpmi ot redro ni ynam tuo raew lliw uoY
flesmih ,stnerap sih
:etal oot abeS kcurts siht tuoba lausunu saw tahW
.nerdlihc doohrobhgien eht gnoma emankcin tsrif sih dedivorp dah
,dlrow eht fo erawanu ,deunitnoc eh oS
,odarodlE yb pots ot nosaer yramirp eht ,spahrep ,saw siht taht dezilaer evah dluow eh
,tsoc dah seohs esoht hcum woh gnillacer
;roloc tnereffid a detniap dna
.rood eht tuo mih dewollof seye kcurtsewa rieht sa gnihctaw ,lleweraf devaw eh
edih ot elbissopmi erew skaeb nacuot—
,gnitoohs ,gnilbbird—
.ti derebmemer eh naht rellams dekool doohrobhgien eht os neve tub
.deen a neeb yllaer reven dah ereht tub
si yrots s’yadot dna
:daeha saw rof emac eh tahw ,oN
gnidliub kcirb a fo elgnatcer defoor-kaep ,wol ,gnol a ediseb dna
.yllacizziuq mih denimaxe ynnaD
eh esuaceb trap egral ni
,hguoht ,yllatnedicnioC
erutaef elbasiugsidnu na htiw seiceps nommocnu na gnieb fo egatnavdasid enO
detpmetta eh teksab yreve ylraen gnidnal
.noitcefnoc kciht eht no gniwehc teerts eht nwod deklaw eh ,hsur on nI
,yltnelis deddon llaw eht evoba ecaf ehT
revo dna pu hcaer
,ycavirp fo mucidom a gnitnaW
.flesruoy etamitserednu t’nod ,oS“
.krowkcirb eht pirg ot
,anitnegrA ni ytimynona retaerg
nur dna llab rieht nodnaba
,semoh ot yaw evag ortnec fo sgnidliub eht ,yllaudarG
,dna rebbur gnicnuob fo
.ti denwo ohw wonk t’ndid ehS
!keew tsal VT no uoy dehctaw eW !hA“
egrulps ciglatson a—tnadnetta s’oksoik eht morf ]ROH-af-la[ rojafla ehcel ed eclud-dna-
,ylsuorogiv deddon zuL elttiL
.pooh sselten a dna
.llab eht thguac nwaf eht ,retal elbmuf feirb A   ”!hctaC“
.elims a otni denrut ylkciuq tub
.lla s’taht ,flesym ot emit emos teg ot ecin saw tI“
.llabteksab nwo sih tuo dellup eh ,eslupmi na nO .reh ot kcab