.ti no pu dekcip srae neek s’igeR tuB
,ni mih fo lla gnikaT
.yad taht ton saw yadoT
,ylnrets deddon igeR
.deb eht tsniaga yltfos gnipmuht liat sih
.dluoc eh dehsiw eH
stsurht s’igeR gnivig
.esle gnihtyna no sucof t’ndluoc ydrA erehw tniop a ot tog noos tI
,kcab s’yerg eht dnuora parw ot rehgih sgel sih desiar eh
”.esoohc ot teg uoY .em si ti ro
.ylwols ti gnikorts
.yrt nac I“  ”.yssem dnA
,edisni og ot devom dna gnihcaorppa ria thgin dloc eht morf derevihs eH
.enoyna nevig reve d’eh ecarbme tsegnorts eht
.nopu smaerd sih tser yllanif dluoc ydrA taht
”.fo kaeps I tahw ton si htaeD“ .eb ot dedeen eH
”?su tuoba sgnos etirw uoy lliW“
.noitseuq txen sih ot noitcaer s’revol sih ees ot raeb ton dluoc eH .yawa dekool ydrA
tsuj t’ndluohs eh wenk eh
otni peed dekool igeR
.rehtegot wolgretfa eht gniyojne dna gnitnap
,mih evael eugnot s’yerg eht tlef eH
.raer sih htiw pu denil
.ydrA ,won su ylno ot layol eb emit teL“
.draobrevo meht fo htob tnes tonk ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”,uoy ot ti evig em tel nehT“  ”.od I“
,fo og tel eh yrrow a saw mih edisni repeed dils taht kcil yrevE
thguoht lanoitar yreve kcab gnithgif
ot demees ecnedifnoc sih—
.htuom s’ydrA otni gnidils eugnot nwo sih
,dias ydrA ”,syawla dna reveroF .ylluF
.emit emos etiuq rof ekops rehtieN
,erom eht lla no mih denrut mih gnidaerps ti fo thguoht ehT
.erutaef yreve ,ruotnoc yreve ,hcni yrevE
,rebmem sih otno emos deruop yletaidemmi eh dna ,saw ti tnasaelp woh ta denediw seye siH
,ifics tuoba seirots etirw ot sekil ohw flow eulb a
.niaga revo dna revo raer sih tsniaga pals tonk s’flow regral eht leef dluoc ydrA
.gnihtaerb s’ydrA dehctam
,elkcuhc ydrA edam ecnedifnoc siH  ”.ti fo erus ma I
sebor s’eulb eht ta gut dna llup ot deunitnoc swap egral siH
,emit siht rehtraf ,niaga tuo nehT
.ti pots dluoc eh erofeb sdrow otni flesti detsefinam
,htaerb peed a koot ydrA  ”.em ot kcab emoC“
.tsehc s’rentrap sih gnibbur ,delims ydrA
,seye sih denepo eH
oot ti wenk igeR wenk eh dna ,siht wenk flow eulb ehT
.wap mrif a htiw kcab sih otno ydrA dehsup dna deb eht otno sgel sih deppilf igeR ,noitom tfiws eno nI
.flesmih gniyojne saw igeR taht yojne etiuq did eh
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.mih woleb thgir htgnel s’ydrA ta kool ot
,tnurg citsaisuhtne na htiW
.nwo sih gnikatrevo ydob gnorts s’igeR fo erew
,rehto koohs ydrA
,mih tsniaga htaerb mraw s’yerg eht leef dluoc ydrA
.desirprus yltnasaelp ,dias yerg eht
.semit lla ta peek ot devirts eh thguoht lanoitar ,raelc eht gnisol ,lortnoc gnisol saw eH .t’ndluoc eh tub
,amard dna ,ysatnaf
,kcen s’yerg eht dnuora smra sih depparw flow eulb ehT
.thgil rieht tsol seye sih dna
,avilas s’revol sih htiw tew gnimoceb kcen sih tlef ydrA
.gniciton neve mih tuohtiw osrot s’flow yerg eht nwod delevart swap etihw siH
”.ma I taht gnihtyrevE
,sevaw nooram esool ni mih tuoba gnuh klis eht fo sdlof ehT
,gnikael sih ediseb tser elzzum s’igeR was neht
ydaer yllanif saw eh yad eht
.yltnelis doots igeR fo erutcip a erehw dnatsthgin eht ta kool ot denrut eH
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,steehs deb eht pirg ot mih desuac tI
.skciw rieht hguorht yawflah ydaerla erew seldnac eht dna
”.eciohc a ekam ot evah lliw uoy erehw yad A
,swoble sih no kcab detser ydrA
”.emit txen rof wonk ot dooG
.oot dliw og mih tel dluoc eh erehw yad a rof dehsiw eh tub—
.ti ees ot desoppus ma I esle woh em lleT“
.daeh sih fo pid ralugnis a htiw htuom sih otni htgnel eritne s’flow rellams eht nekat dah igeR
,traH ydrA yb ”noinueR“
.igeR ot ti evag eh nehT
,sredluohs s’yerg eht dezeeuqs eH
,mih gnivael morf noissap fo doolf eht pots t’ndluoc
”.dnoces a em evig tsuJ
saw sihT     .rehtegoT
,kaew saw ti emit siht tub ,dnim s’ydrA otni yaw sti tperc niaga yrroW
,elims dna seye s’yerg eht no desucof yllanif eh nehW
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”…uoy tnaw I …I ?…ew naC“
.ecaf s’ydrA dekcil dna
.gnipsag ,dias ydrA ”…igeR…R“
.rebmem gnihctiwt
.ti devol eh tub ,redduhs ot flow eulb eht desuac mih edisni hself tew fo gnileef neddus ehT
.ereht pots t’ndid igeR tuB
”noinueR“   yojne esaelP
.dias flow eulb eht
.sehcni wef tsal eht ni dehsup igeR sa xaler ot deganam yllanif ydrA
.stnurg delffum neewteb dias igeR ”,tey gnittonk dessucsid t’nevah eW“
,seye eht ni flow regral eht dekool eh nehT
.mih morf hgis yhtaerb rehtona gninrae
dessik eh elihw sehctulc rieht morf flow eht eerf ot gniyrt
level emos no kcab gnidloh saw igeR wenk eH
.liat sih ot nwod yaw eht lla gninnur srevihs gnidnes ,rae sih otni dehtaerb rentrap sih ”,rebmemer I“
.sneppah tahw rettam on
.ti kcatta ot depmuj ydrA dna
.netfo os sthguoht sih deugalp taht yrrow eht leef ot evah ton ot
.ezis elbaeganamnu tsomla na ot hcterts flesmih tlef ydrA
eno siht piks nac uoy
?em esaeler nac uoy kniht uoY“ .mih tep ydrA
.erom detnaw eh taht wonk igeR gnittel
,ereht dial meht fo owt ehT .detsuahxe
.em fo dloh koot emit erehw s’tahT“
.rebma nedlog a dna ,elprup peed a—
.flow regral eht no dliw og flesmih gnittel fo thguoht eht ta gnihsulb
,enog tub lla saw thgiL
spih s’ydrA debbarg eH
.sraet s’ydrA yawa depiw eh sa denworf igeR
;kcab mih dleh reven igeR
,riah gnol s’ydrA delffur ezeerb rehtonA
,mrof s’rentrap sih dnuora ecnad thgil eldnac eht dehctaw ydrA
.klis suoicerp eht niur ot gnitnaw ton
.mih ecaf ot dnuora rellams eht denrut flow regral ehT
,yssem teg ot gniog erew sgniht gniwonK
.lauqe na sa mih taert ot troffe gnorts a hcus a edam dah yerg eht esuaceb
.riah citcra gnol s’ydrA hguorht nar rehto eht elihw
.suoires eb ot tnaw t’ndid eH
ot detnaw eh fi sivlep s’eulb eht hsurc ylisae yrev dluoc yerg eht—
enog saw igeR sraey eht ni denrael eh sgniht erew erehT
.ydrA ot gnitadimitni
.kcab mih degguh flow regral ehT
,redluohs sih ta deggut yltneg wap A
,edis ym yb yats ll’uoy taht em esimorP“
.lotipac eht fo tser eht morf ecalap renni eht detarapes taht etag nori taerg eht ta gnitniop ,derepsihw eh
,deksa yerg eht ”?yako uoy erA“
”…em ekaT…T“  ”.oot eM“
.ydob sih niatnoc ot elba ylerab erew taht sebor deroloc krad ni ynoclab eht tsniaga denael flow eulb ehT
,semit ta ,saw ecnedifnoc dehsabanu sih tub
,tfahs sih dnuora esolc spil s’yerg eht tlef eH
.flow eulb rellams eht otno ,ylwols ,despalloc eH
.mih ffo gnidils sebor sih tlef ydrA
,etatiseh ton did igeR
.gninettalf srae sih ,yawa kool ot dah eH
,mih delddarts igeR
lliw I“ .ekops dna kcab s’yerg eht dehctarcs neht
pu flesmih gnidloh wap eno
?dnop kcud eht dnuora rehto hcae esahc ot desu ew dnA
.ti detnaw I .eb t’noD“
,seye sih denepo ydrA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.tsrif ta yawflah ylnO
.hteet dettirg sih hguorht tuo naom ot ydrA gnisuac
.derepmihw flow eulb eht
.hguoht gnol rof dnim sih ni yats t’ndid thguoht tahT  .ecno tsuJ
.draytruoc eht ni eert hcaep eht rednu gnixaler tneps eh stnemom eht ot kcab nekat saw eH
.thguoht taht ni flesmih tsol eH
.yrruFoS no krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.dnatsthgin eht fo reward pot eht nepo dellup dna
,seye desolc-flah htiW
.htaerb sih rednu dias ydrA
.retfa yletaidemmi gniteem spil rieht
.htaerb yvaeh ,gnitnaw a htiw
”.enon ees I erehw eciohc a ees uoY“
.nwo sih ni swap s’eulb eht gnidloh ,deb eht no revol sih ediseb tas neht
,ti detnaw eh tuB
.ssik etanoissap a ni mih sdrawot flow eulb eht gnillup ,daeh
.ssem ykcits toh a ni stnorf rieht fo htob gnitaoc
.hcamots sih tsniaga hctiwt a gnileef
.erusaelp ni tuo deraor igeR sa tsuj
,sedisni sih tsniaga sserp tonk eht gnileef ,ydrA dna
ni mih fo lla ekat yllanif ot gniganam
.tnurg a htiw dednopser igeR  ”?ekawa uoY ?geR“
.rentrap sih gnittep ,delims tsuj ydrA
,nemodba sih ffo ebor sih fo trap tpews ydrA
…haeY“ .ykahs saw htaerb s’ydrA
,eno hcae til yletaciled ydrA
.tsujda ot emit elttil yrev ydrA gnivael
.ffins kciuq a edisni diuqil eht evag dna laiv eht dekrocnu yerg ehT
.nuh ,yrroS“ ,delkcuhc igeR
.ecnatsiser elttil yrev
,flow eulb elttil eht otni dees sih fo epor retfa epor depmup igeR
”?ksa uoy od yhW .seY“
ti fo ffo gnillaf ebor esool sih
”.niaga uoy dnuof dna
,elttil a ecarbme sih denesool yerg ehT
.em evoL“  ”.ydrA ,gnihtynA“
.rethgit reve revol sih degguh ylpmis dna
.ttub s’igeR tsniaga werg rebmem nwo s’ydrA elihw ,hcamots sih tsniaga gnikop saw pit s’igeR
”,igeR ,gnihtemos em esimorP“
—iteirav laiceps sekam ohw ytic eht ni wonk I wollef a s’erehT“  ”.ylil enola teL“
mhtyhr larutan rieht otni llef yeht nehT
.kcab rehtruf mih dehsup dna
,ecnart sih fo tuo deppans flow rellams ehT
.daerb dekab fo llems eht ti htiw gniyrrac
s’ydrA fo edis eht no wap a decalp eH
.wam mraw sih fo tuo gnippils rebmem s’ydrA
,tnemom a rof thguoht flow eulb ehT
,mih ta dekool igeR
.eros elttil a gnileef m’I
,elzzum sih tsap tpews ezeerb A
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.rorepme na fo dedeen si tahw
”.em rof hguone esool er’uoy erus ekam tsum I
,dias flow eulb eht
,htaerb a ekat ot ydrA decrof erusserp neddus ehT
.sih ni swap s’ydrA fo eno gnidloh ,dias igeR
.sllab sih woleb deppid
.ti etanimulli ot dedeen seldnac eht lla thgil ot emit emos koot ti os ,moordeb egral a saw tI
.trapa rehtraf daerps yllacitamotua sgel sih sa seye sih nepo ot gniganam ,deddon ydrA
.thgiew sih htiw ecalp ni mih gnikcol
.ecnatsni taht ni dehsad saw
.ydob reppu sih hcterts ot tnemom a gnikat
”.htaed gnipacse on si ereht
,ylthgit rentrap sih dezeeuqs ydrA
dnim lamirp sih ni tfel sthguoht ylno eht litnu
.skcil dna skcep ni
.roolf eht ot meht werht dna mih rednu morf tuo sebor eht dellup igeR
,dednopser yerg eht erofeb stsurht erom wef a koot tI
”.sruo sa eurt sa dna taerg sa
.mottob s’ydrA otni spih sih gnillor ,ni kcab dehsup eh nehT
.mih evoba gnimool ydob lufituaeb s’rentrap sih ta gnikool peek t’ndluoc eh erehw tniop a ot mih deretsulf ti dna
,daeh sih koohs ydrA
,derednow ydrA tuB
denruter I ecnis ,gnieb ym fo rebif yreve htiw
dnuorg eht no gniyl ydaerla erew sebor s’rentrap sih taht was eH
”,ti otni stnecs esufni dluoc yeht wonk t’ndid I“
.retsaf ylthgils ,ni kcab neht
,detcarter sregnif s’flow regral ehT
.redrah mih dednuop igeR sa retrohs dna rehgih emoceb ot snaom s’ydrA rof gnol ekat t’ndid tI
.rehtruf gnillaf sebor sih
.did yllausu eh ekil liatynop eht ni toN
,neethgie denrut igeR yad eht dezilairomem tI
”,igeR ,em llet nehT“
,gnol ekat t’ndid tI
,edisni flesmih fo tsal eht teg ot gniyrt
,repeed mih ssik ot ecnahc a igeR gnivig
,revo saw kcohs laitini eht retfA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”,struh ti fi wonk em teL
.cirbaf eht fo emos gniraet swalc sih
,sebor s’ydrA morf tonk tsal eht gniytnU
,stsurht s’igeR tsniaga kcab dehsup eh os
.hcuot eht morf denethgiarts eh sa
”.loof on era uoy dna ,yaw taht ti ees dluow loof a ylnO“
,nettalf ot demees srae siH
.gnihtaerb sih ydaets ot gniyrt ,seye sih desolc flow eulb ehT
,sehcnuah sih no tis ot pu esor ylwols igeR
.yltneg swap s’ydrA dezeeuqs flow yerg ehT
.wap s’ydrA morf redloh eldnac eht gnikat
,mih dnuora sevlesmeht parw swap s’flow yerg eht evah ot ,meht ni tsol teg ot yldab os detnaw eH
.laiv ssalg ynihs a tuo gnillup erofeb dnoces a rof dnuora delbmuf eH
evol a swonk flesreh erutaN rehtoM taht os
.mra sih gnibbarg ,dias ydrA
?spup erew ew nehw rebmemer uoy oD“  traH ydrA yb
gnirevawnu dna gnorts gnihtemoS .noitadnuof A
”.ti ekil uoy dalg m’I“
.kniht ot tnemom a rof desuap igeR
.mih hguorht gnilppir erusaelp tnes taht eno tew ,mraw A
.hsilpmocca dluow yeht tahw dna ,meht fo yrots A
.hcum oot saw niap ehT .tuo pat ot dah ydrA
seye sih desolc eH .meht tel eH
.dias eh ”,detimilnu era evah ew syad eht dneterp t’ndluow uoy hsiw I“
,daeh sih detlit ydrA
”,esolc…m’I ,igeR“
seye aimorhcoreteh sih ni thguac gnitteg syar s’tesnus eht
flesmih ot peek d’eh thguoht a neeb evah dluow tahw
.og ot detnaw eh sa raf sa tnew ydrA
”,ti tnaw uoy taht leef nac I“
.pihsrorepme laitnetop eht rof
,htaerb peed a htiW
.thginot nwod erow eh hcihw
.rebmem sih dnuora parw eugnot eht tlef ydrA
.kcohs rehtona saw ereht neht dnA
.htaerb delffum a tuo gnittel
,gnihtyreve esol ew fi ,sllaf yks eht fi ,selbmurc modgnik eht fI
.rorepme eb lliw I“
.yad yreve taht flesym ksa I“
.taht ta delkcuhc igeR
,tuo flesti denrub ylraen dah erif gniraor ehT
.mih ot nwod ydob s’igeR gnillup ni emit on detsaw ydrA
,seinoclab s’ecalap eht fo eno no enorht eht erofeb gnidnats saw eH
,hguorht dna hguorht
”.emit emos rof kcuts eb ll’eW“
”.uoy tnaw I ,sdoG .ydaer m’I…I“
,traH ydrA yb ”noinueR“
seye sih denepo eh sa seenk dna swoble no saw eH
.niaga worg htgnel s’rentrap sih tlef ydrA nehw elbatrofmocnu teg ot detrats ylno tI
.naorg a htiw pu flesmih gnihsup ,dias igeR
”.em tsniaga doog os leef uoY“
”…esaelp…em edisni uoy deen I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ydob s’igeR otni kcab dehsup yltneg dna
.raer sih ta gniggut eht tlef ydrA nehT
.mih erofeb yerg fo aes eht ni gnikat
.llew sa reduol gnitnurg igeR yb dezisahpme saw sihT
ydrA gnirehtoms ,niaga despalloc igeR
.hcuot a tsuj elballys tsal eht tuo gniward ,dias eh ”…ydrA“
.eulb eht tsniaga pu desserp
,flow eltneg a saw igeR
,swap sih ni flow eulb eht dleh dna
,nwod denael igeR
.gnilkcuhc dna daeh s’ydrA fo edis eht gnibbur ,flow rellams eht ta nwod dekool eH
.kcen sih delzzun dna dexaler igeR
.pu kaeps ot ydrA desuac raer sih fo sseneros eht ,yllautnevE
gut driht eht retfa dna ,kciht oot llits saw tonk ehT
,swalc sih htiw sebor s’ydrA ta deggut eH
,dnal eht ssorca ylf yeht sa gnis lliw sdribgnos taht seidolem etirw
srood ynoclab eht desolc flow eulb ehT
.sevlow owt eht neewteb deniamer htmraw tub
,ydrA nihtiw detarebrever sdrow s’igeR
”.ereht eb ll’uoy wonk ot deen I
,spih sih debbarg igeR
,deeps pu gnikcip detrats yerg ehT
stnurg s’igeR ni flesmih tsol eH
.kcen sih fo kcab eht nwod dessik eh sa
.redluohs sih otni gnilzzun
.hcuot eht otni denael flow eulb ehT
.tsehc s’flow eulb eht ot delevart elzzum sih sa
.seye eht ni mih gnikool ,pu nihc s’ydrA detlit flow yerg ehT
.regnif dias htiw tuo flow eulb eht gnihcterts emit elttil yrev tneps eh dna ,raer sih tsniaga regnif detaoc a debbur dah igeR
,ot gniyrt deppots eH
”?uoy selbuort taht ti si tahw ,llet yarp nehT“
.gniog erif a tog igeR sa
.lufrewop ssel yna meht ekam t’ndid tub
,snottub s’ydrA lla desserp yaw eht ni rof derac leef mih ekam dna mih erusaelp ot drah os gniyrt dna
ecnedifnoc s’igeR
?og flesmih tel eh dluohs raf woh
.wap a htiw igeR gnidael
.seye sih gnisolc ,denaom ydrA ”…hhhhO
,kcen s’yerg eht dnuora smra sih depparw ydrA
,ot desu saw eh tahw erew sehcni elpuoc tsrif ehT
.nevaeh morf traeh sih tpek taht
.oot erom detnaw igeR taht leef dluoc eh ,nwod rehtruF
.shtnom ni emit tsrif eht rof gniggaw liat sih
.delims dna dehsulb ,siht gniees ,ydrA
,flow yerg larutan a ,igeR  ”.su fO
.resolc mih gnillup
.regnol yna pu flesmih dloh t’ndluoc igeR
”.uoy esimorp I tahT“
.snaom thgil s’ydrA detnemelpmoc erusaelp fo stnurg peed sih dna ,ecap ecin a ta gniog saw igeR ,hguoht ,nooS
”.edis ruoy yb yats d’I desimorp I“
”?t’nod yeht fi dna…dnA“
”.neht si ti edis ym yB“
.ylthgils os reve psarg sih gninethgit
.rethgirb eht lla enihs osrot thgit sih fo ruf hcamots etihw eht gnikam
ssik eht ekorb igeR erofeb htaehs s’flow yerg eht gniregnif ot tog neve eH
.niaga revo dna revo ezis eht ot tsujda ot dah eh sa
”.rehtegot tuo yenruoj siht edir ew dna ,sneppah tahw rettam on ,edis ruoy yb dnats lliw I nehT“
”.taht tbuod ton od I“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.elpoep eseht wonk I
.seye yretaw htiw mih ta pu dekool ydrA
”,llew sa gnihtemos em esimorp tsum uoy tuB“
,eno eht ot desu saw eh thguoht ydrA sa noos sA
,eripme eht tuoba sgniht—
.rebmem sih dnuora parw ot gninruter
.tib a gninettalf srae sih ,dias igeR ”,yrroS“
,elur ot yaw reporp eht
.htaehs s’igeR morf pu gnipmuj wap sih
.epoh htiw mih gnillif
.rof dnats I gnihtyreve ni eveileb lliw yeht
,gnihgual morf flesmih peek t’ndluoc flow eulb llams ehT
.rehto eht fo og tel ot gnitnaw rehtien ,elihw a rof ereht dial owt ehT
.htuom sih morf gnidolpxe erusaelp fo stuohs eht elfits ot kcen s’igeR otni elzzum sih gniyrub
”?uoy hctac ot eganam I did woH“
”,uoy gnisol ma I taht raef I ,traehteewS“
.htiw ti llif ot sdrow fo gnikniht
psag ydrA gnikam ydaerla erew snoitom ehT
;mih no sucof ot ydrA rof stnemom wef a koot tI
,daeha yal taht segnellahc eht tuoba gniwonknu dna tbuod hcum os saw ereht erofeb erehW
yerg eht rednu morf tuo sgel sih dellup ydrA
.esimorp a saw ereht won
.saw eh lla saw taht ekil tca
,kcab dna pu meht gnihsup
od I sa llew sa wonk uoY“ .sdnuob on wonk
.yaw gnivol a hcus ni mih fo erac ekat rentrap sih gnihctaw
”.nevaeh ot resolc tlef reven ev’I“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.tuo flesmih gnillup nageb dna keehc eht no mih dessik igeR  ”.esaelp ,wols oG“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.mih gniregnif tpek igeR nehw drah saw ti tub ,ydob sih xaler ot gniyrt ,delahxe ydrA
.niaga rentrap sih htiw seye gnikcol
.noitarbelec eht dednetta ohw elpoep fo sdnasuoht eht ta gnivaw
”.su dnatsrednu ton lliw yehT .elpoep ruoY
,mhtyhr s’igeR decarbme ydrA sA
”?tcerroc ,sgnos ruoy lla etirw uoY“
daeh s’igeR fo gnibbob eht—
sthguoht dna smaerd sih ni tub ,remrofrep a ylno saw flow eulb eht ,ytilaer nI
.daeh sih morf sthguoht tnasaelp erom
.yrots tnereffid a llet dluow taht sdroW
.spsag nwo sih neewteb deilper ydrA ”,em tonk nac uoY“
.lla ti detnaw eH
”.su neewteb emoc lliw gnihtoN
,dias flow yerg eht
,stsurht sih nwod dewols igeR
.sih tsniaga spil s’rentrap sih fo hcuot eht derovas ydrA
,sebyam eht dna sfi-tahw eht kcab gnithgif ,tbuod eht kcab gnithgif
.igeR ,erutuf ruoy ni si yad tnatropmi nA“ .nageb neht
,eripme eht si tI“
,shgiht s’eulb eht fo dloh koot swap sih nehT
.gnikael trats ot meht fo htob gnisuac
,ylthgit mih degguh eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ti tuoba kniht neve dluoc eh erofeb spil sih depacse naom A
.eulb eht otni flesmih gnihsup nageb ylwols neht
,srae sih dniheb dehctarcs dna daeh s’rentrap sih debbur flow eulb ehT
,ti fo ssenissem lacisyhp eht ekil ylirassecen t’ndid eh hguoht dna
tfahs s’revol sih sa dehctaw ydrA
.tuo level ot demees yllanif ti litnu erom dna erom dna erom mih hcterts ot demees tsuj wef txen eht tub
,enut nettogrof-gnol a
.mih evoba saw ydob reppu s’igeR niaga seye sih denepo eh nehw dna
,deb eht raen dnatsthgin a no nwod ti decalp eH
nwod denael eh nehT
”.tsap era noitarapes ruo fo syad eht roF
,noitceffa eht ffo thgif ot deganam yllanif ydrA nehW
elzzum s’igeR sa ,desufnoc ylthgils ,dehctaw ydrA
.dnim sih no saw tahw yas ot yaw thgir eht fo kniht ot gniyrt
,htaehs nwo sih tsniaga dils rentrap sih fo sllab kciht ehT
gniggut sih desaec igeR
.tsiaw s’ydrA elddarts ot pu delwarc igeR
”,igeR ,ereht uoy ot eybdoog dias I“
,drawrof dehsup dna kcab deraer igeR emit hcaE
.sredluohs s’ydrA debbarg eh sa tib a delbmuf eh
.spih s’ydrA gnibbur
.tniop siht ta dnim sih ni tfel saw ereht lla saw tahT .stsurht dna
.tsehc s’ydrA nwod dekcil dna
,sedis rieht ot llef sbmil s’ydrA
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
,rae s’igeR otni derepsihw ydrA
,elpoep ym ylurt era yeht fI“
.evol fo noisserpxe taerg a saw
.hctiwt liat sih ekam ot hguone saw sdrawretfa emac taht noitcus eht dna
.htuom sih morf detaerter igeR ,did eh sA
.meht fo owt eht revo lla gnikael tfahs nwo sih
,pirg sih xaler ot yrt ro flesmih esitsahc dluow flow eulb eht ,yliranidrO
,elims ydrA edam tahT  ”.uoy tuobA
.igeR ,esimorp I“
.noitisop elbatrofmoc erom a otni mih dniheb swollip eht degnarra igeR sa tsehc s’flow regral eht nwod walc a nar neht
”.ereht nwod thgiR
sredluohs s’ydrA ot delevart swap s’igeR
.pu kcab dekrep srae s’igeR
,peek ot nrows ev’I esimorp a siT’“ .seye gniwolg esoht
.tsiaw sih dloh ot nwod gnidils swap s’flow yerg eht
gnimmuh nageb eh nehT
,spih s’ydrA debbarg eH
.taht leef dluoc igeR depoh eh ,saw rentrap sih sa gnorts sA
,owt ot pu ti depmub igeR
.tib a nips ot demees moor eht