emit siht ,tnahpmuirt erew yeht spahrep rO
,ti ta dehctulc dnim sih sa noos sa tsomla hcae gnidracsid
.krims lufeur a flesmih dewolla xof eht ,taht
,wodahs sti ni llewd ot hguone emat tey dna
tfarc eht fo evol eht rof siht gniod m’I
,ecaf sih deiduts nevar
,dnim eht stcilffA…“
noitazilivic fo ekoy eht tsiser ot hguone dliw erif fo lehsub elttil a :elbatpada dna
.cinut nrow sih dniheb ylpmil gnignah
erusaelP“	  .yltnetsisni erom ,nevar eht dias
,ecneidebo enituor gniriuqer ,sgniht gnivil lla fo retsaM .tnelis dna elbisivni ,nurtuo ro
,thgindim sa kcalb srehtaef fo riap a ylno gnihctac ,sgniw fo yrrulf eht ta walc a depiws xof eht xelfer yB
.reh ecaf ot delrihw dranyeR	  ”.gnikees
.deknilb ylerem drib ehT
.gniraelc tilnoom a otni delbmuts ,tnedicca yb etiuq ,dna
,nam dna tsaeb detseb dah eH
,straeh fo tseilwol eht neve ni rednit ydaer dnuof won redrosid dna tbuod fo serif eht erehw
.seye kcalb ydaeb htiw mih gnihctaw
.no saw drib elttil eht edis esohw erus eb t’ndluoc dranyeR—
,erom ecno ffo koot drib eht ,os did eh sA
uoY“	  .derepsihw eh
.hcnarb a no yltneitap gnittis keT dnuof eh
I“	  ”.sdrac eht fo lla gnidloh ot desu rehtar ma I dnA“
eh nehW .erif etihw tniaf htiw dezalb srats eht ,nik s’nevar eht fo dnasuoht a dleh evah dluoc ti kcalb os pordkcab a tsniagA
evila em peek ot ylerem devres
dranyeR“	  .ecnayonna dipet otni delkcirt ylkciuq sniev s’xof eht ni raef ehT
.degnahc dah eh ,tey dnA
,ria thgin eht otni edaf gnos reh fo seton tsal eht
ehT	  .deksa xof ehT
”,nevar elttil
…shtiaf mrof dna seimra yllar ot elba
.gnikees erew uoy ecivda eht uoy nevig ydaerla ev’I ,sneppah ti
.sreknab fo sraggeb dna sgnik fo kcom edam dah
era uoy ohw ot sa eriuqni ron ,selddir erom rof ksa ton did I“
.deraos traeh s’xof
…tI“	  ”.gnimrahc etiuq eno taht dnuof I ,noitalosnoc yna s’ti
ehT	  .rae sih ta gnihctarcs ,derettum dranyeR
,ezorf drib ehT ”!kcab
.dniw eht gnidir kcalb fo hsalf a gnihctac eye sih ,detsiwt
:meht dedulcxe eh sa tsaf sa tsomla seitilibissop hguorht gnitros
.eulav sti ycnerruc evag taht ecnesse yrev eht
er’uoY“	  .taorht sih deraelc dranyeR
”.secaps ytpme ni sllif dna
rehpotsirhC tniaS fo noilladem dedaf ,nrow eht gniregniF
ehT	  .dednetni tsirhC suseJ droL doog eht sa devas eb thgim lla taht os
.llits deniamer dranyeR nehw eno redlob dnoces a neht
.htaenrednu ruf tessur eht ta hctarcs ot tah sih gnitfil ,dias dranyeR ”,thgir lla ,hO“	  ”.nigeb yam uoy
.sdrow s’nevaR eht gnirednop
fI“	  ”—em evig llahs uoy ,selddir ruoy rewsna I fI“ .deilper xof eht
,soahc gnikraps ni trap sih deyalp dah eh sega
.sterces sti rof noitaerc gnigderd ni evitceffe rehtar nworg dah yeht etal fo sa dna—
,ydolem eht thguac tsrif srae sih nehw tub
”.xoF eht dranyeR ,ecitsuj uoy od ot liaf yleritne ton seod noitatuper ruoy sraeppa tI“
,denialpxe xof eht
sih oT	  .detaefed dnuos ot tseb sih gniyrt ,yltfos erom dias eh ”,esaelP“
htym rof moor gnildniwd-reve tfel dah
,spohsib fo eritta tnagavartxe eht ni mih dehtolc stnasaep
,ylluferac denetsil dranyeR	  ”.ylppa
,tnemom a rof sselnoitom tas nevaR ehT	  ”.emoh gnitsal a
ehT	  .delworg xof eht ”,ti htiw no teg s’teL“	  .redluohs s’dranyeR no gnithgil erofeb gniraelc eht gnilcric ,ria eht otni tpael drib elttil ehT .keT dias
ehT	  .elddir txen sih gnitivni ,ylthgils daeh reh dewob ehS ”.doog yreV“
”,snoitan dna nem sa rennam emas eht ni hcum eid ot ycnednet a sah tiW“	  .deksa eh ”?tiW“	  .dworc a
.flesmih ot derepsihw dranyeR
.elkcuhc lanif a tuo gnittel
”,ekil dluohs I sa llew os ylraen
.ti devol dah dranyeR ,tcaf eht nwonk dah eh sa gnol sa
.nekorb neeb ton dah niahc eht taht ,esirprus sih ot ,dnuof dna
ehT	  .yldlob dias eh ”,regnuH“
dah eh muinnellim a naht erom
.gnizinomres rehtruf yna llatserof ot dnah a desiar
”,xoF eht dranyeR ,hguone llew uoy wonk I
,tirw yliad era senil sseltnuoc sA“
”.taht tseggus dluow uoy gnipoh saw
”,yaw tcerrocni llits tey dna
”—spahrep neht ,ylohcnalem ton s’ti fI“
ehT	  .ni tuc nevaR eht
effilcyW dna suH yb nwos sdees ehT
,part a fo sngis rof trela niamer ot devloser eH
,sdeedsim sih denmad yeht sa yrehcuabed sih ni dethgiled klofsnwoT
.gnikam-elddir fo tra elohw eht ot yek eht saw ,mih ot demees ti ,hcihw
.dranyeR ,nem fo sdnim eht ni nrob erew uoy esuaceb si
,ezag s’namow eht teem ot pu gnikool
,tnatiseh a htiw deilper nevaR
tibbaR eht dranyeR ro
,llacer ot derac eh taht seman erom rednu eporuE ssorca kram sih tfel dah eh tnuoc dnoyeb sraey roF
.lrans a htiw noitseuq sih ffo tib dranyeR ”—uoy od
,nopu detnuoc syawla dah eh tnatsnoc eno eht ,egnahC
.dennirg eh ,sselehtenoN
,ecalaP nehcaA fo sllah deirots eht ot naegeA gnilkraps eht fo serohs eht morf
dethgil ,nrohtwah a fo wodahs gnimool eht otni pu delias keT
,enirhs tnelis A .nwonknu sdnal rof llac fo trop A .enots fo nworc ,lessev nehtraE“
seipgam ekil gnirettacs sthguoht sih ,drib taerg eht ta pu derats dranyeR ”…I“	  ”.era uoy tahw deksa I—
fI“	  ”?amard fo esnes ruoy s’erehW .yltcerroc gnisseug erofeb rewsna gnorw dnoces a nevig tsael ta evah dluoc uoy ,wonk uoY“ .desuap eH ”.seY…“ .gnipmuls sredluohs ,hgis tuo-nward a esool tel dranyeR	  ”!yromem—hO“	  ”...oN“
.hcnarb ybraen a no nwod delttes dah swadkcaj ydnar eht fo eno taht dnuof eh
.thguoht hcum ti nevig yllaer reven ev’I ,tsenoh eb oT .wonk t’nod I“
.snediam gnihsad htiw secnaillad fo htraed on dah ev’uoy erus
;stnahcrem dna sgnik ,stseirp dna slareneg ot rewop evag tI
”,ycnerruC“	  ”.htap reporp eht no eb ot raeppa od uoy hguohT
…esuaceB“	  ”?taht si yhW
,sdrow eht tuo ekam ton dluoc dranyeR
tah sih fo mirb eht detfihs dranyeR
,ffo deliart eh ”…uoy did woH“
”?egdelwonK…“	  .ehtaerb ot gnirad yldrah
.nik sih dna mih ot
gnitteL	  .pets yb pets esir doolb
,ezag s’namow eht dewollof dranyeR nehw dna
tahW“	  .yllufeur dettimda eh
.ylevitisiuqni daeh sti dekcoc neht
tA“	  .eniltsaoc naemdaC eht tsniaga evaw yb evaw flesti gnihsad
rof dna ,dlrow s’nam a ni xof a saw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
,gniniarts seye ,delbmum eh
fI“	  ”.em pleh t’nseod tahT“
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.gnissim noilladem sih dnif ot taorht sih ot decar dnah s’dranyeR	  .kaeb sti ni erusaert revlis a gnihctulc
?dloh retskcirt a did esoprup rehgih tahw
toN“	  .derad reve dah nem wef yaw a ni ezag sih gniteem ,mih ecaf ot denrut ehS
”?keT ,ereht t’nsi ,eye eht steem naht uoy ot erom
ecnO	  .eye sih fo renroc eht morf nevaR eht gniyduts ,kcab knarhs neht
,tuobadnuor ,egnarts a
ot ria looc eht gnitset
,htiw gnipleh m’I tahw wonk t’nod I fi uoy pleh yltcaxe t’nac I lleW“
.thgir nwo sih ni retskcirt detnelat a etiuq eb ot nevorp sah ,kniht dluohs I ,ohw ,nam fo gnihton yas ot—
,nem fo straeh eht ni gnillewd
?eb ti dluoc tahw neht ,esoht fo yna t’nsaw ti fi tub—
”,etirohcna ydoolb a ekil sdoow eht ni elbmar loof a ot netsil ot tsuj spahrep rO“
,bmil eert yldnips eht gnola poh evitatnet ,trohs a koot nevar
eH	  .tnemaciderp tnerruc sih fo
.deilper xof eht
.seye s’drib taerg eht ni decnad feihcsiM
gnisolc ylwols saw dlrow eht
,sehcnarb sti fo eno no
”,seY“	  ”.tnemllifluf retaerg rof gnignol
.erom ecno mih erofeb doots
ehT	  .esaenu sih dewollaws eh ,kcab sih dniheb sdnah sih gnipsalC
reH	  ”.eulc a t’nevah I
.tsae decnalg eh nopuerehw
tel neht ,evom txen sih no ylluferac thguoht xof ehT
!ssenriaf tuoba em ot gnihcaerp xoF eht
sih oT ”.ti fo flah eht wonk t’nod uoy ,gnilrad ,hO“
,daeh sih pota ruf esool eht hguorht dnah dewalc a deggard eh ,tah sih gnitfiL .seye
.ot deen eht leef eh did rehtien tub
egnellahc sti ta klab ot deliaf reven dah dniknam ,nwonknu eht fo seiretsym eht ni delever eh erehW .cigam dna
yrevE	  .ereh mih del dah taht nevar eht sa kcalb riah reh
.hteet dehcnelc hguorht dessih xof eht ”,t’nsi yllaer
ecnirp delppot tnasaep
”,keT“	  .swaperof depsalc sih no elzzum sih gnitser
.delims ehs ,niaga
,erutats rellams sti morf trapa
”…ecaep no sdeef dna regnad sdiova taht
;gninnuc sih gnidual elihw elpmaxe sih tsniaga nerdlihc rieht denraw dna
.srenroc bup til-mid morf
.tif meht fo enon tub …raef
,tnias dedaeh-god eht fo noilladem eht ot wap sih evord noitarepsed tub ,reyarp rof eno t’nsaw eH .ylsselepoh ffo deliart sthguoht s’xof eht ereH
,dnamed I ecneidebo enituoR ,sgniht gnivil lla fo retsam ehT
:tnorfnoc ot mih decrof dah lavaehpu neddus siht taht nosiop gnikrul a
tsif a otni wap dehctertstuo sih delruc dranyeR
I“	  .yks nretsae eht ni redloms ot gninnigeb tsuj erew nwad fo stnih tsrif eht litnu
,erif no tibbarkcaj a naht rekciuq tiw a dna leets derepmet naht reprahs eugnot a htiW
llA“	  .seye reh deworran nevaR
.thgin retniw gnol a no llafwons ekil ,dloc dna tfos seton eht
.thgin eht fo secart tsal eht otni gnitlem
hsurb deppit-etihw eht ot
.ylwols deknilb neht
?laed lanrefni na fo rettel eht ot yltsujnu uoy dnib ot tuo
.sdees rof gnihcraes demuser dna
.worb sih deworruf
.eliug lufeelg htiw swodahs eht morf sgnirts ta deggut eh
,iksaL rimisaC yb
,reduol werg gnos eht sa klaw eltneg a ot dewols eH
dranyeR	  ”.snoziroh laicos ruoy nedaorb ot deen ylurt uoy ,ssendooG“
,ylreporp rehto eht nmad ot thgir eht rof
gnihtemoS“ .raeh t’ndluoc xof eht mhtyhr a ot gnibbob daeh
”,tab A“	  ”—uoy ees ot ekil d’I“
”,keT“	  .dias nevaR eht
:deticer ,ydolem fo tnih a deirrac taht eciov a ni
.seye gniknilbnu htiw mih ta derats nevaR ehT	  ”?yllaeR… ?selddiR…“ .daeh sih dekcoc dranyeR	  ”.nwo ym fo selddir wef a rewsna ot elba era uoy fi
roF“	  ”…rewsna eht si …taht ,seY“
ehS	  ”.dnah ym epacse gnol rof tonnaC ,skcirt sih lla htiw ,nam neve dnA
.elims a fo ecnalbmes a otni dekcarc kaeb s’nevaR
,ytuaeb reh yb detavitpac eb tub pleh ton dluoc dranyeR tey dna—esruoc fo ,seno ylemoh eht rof tpecxe—evitcartta saw tem xof eht namow
”,dnamed I ecneidebo enituoR“
.niks enipluv yltcnitsid raew dna ,eno flesruoy eman uoy hguoht ,xof a uoy era rehtien dna …nam a ton ylniatrec tsom era uoy ,lleW“	  ”.thguoht
hcae rof eerhT .sesseug eerht teg I
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
ehT	  .deksa yllanif ehs
.mih dniheb saw tnemesuma suoucav rof emit eht tub
roF	  .skcolf ylurnu rieht fo sgar delggardeb eht ni mih dekaolc spohsib dna
,erutan yltsaeb nommoc rieht ot gniwo ,fi sa
.hguone riaF“	  ”.od htob eW .elddir
eH	  .sralucitrap eht gninimreted saw
,ylwol eht revo egdelwonk ruoy gnidrol no neek os mees uoy
,noom gninaw eht derucsbo ehs ,mih revo gnimooL
,stcejbus elbissop fo thguoht eH
erofeb reve naht retsaf gnignahc saw taht dlrow A
,yllooc deilper nevaR eht
egar dna tsul tuo delur ylerus taht ,evol naht ylohcnalem ot resolc saw ti fi :ylluferac sdrow reh derednop
”!yregavas ym rof em hsinomda dna
,yltcniccus erom ti tup
dnA	  .yawyna ,tsomdnih eht ekat liveD eht tel ot retteb syawla saw ti
.ees elgae eht nac roN raeh tonnac tibbar eht hcaorppa yM
.sworg ti ecaep ni ,seelf regnad morF .seog dna semoc ti ,flow suonevar A“
,tseug ym sA
,nevar elttil regae eht retfa deirruh
,hO“	  ”.ydal ym ,tem ev’ew eveileb t’nod
:spot eert denekrad eht dnoyeb gnizalb noom revlis eht sdrawot kaeb ynobe reh gninilcni
dranyeR	  ”.xoF ,nerdlihc ym fo eno fo tseretni eht detcartta ev’uoy sraeppa tI“
sih ot regnif dewalc a gnippat ,detniuqs eh
,ria eht ni gnuh eciov
uoY“	  .nevaR eht ta ylsuoituac dekool eH ”?evol…“—nihc
,egar ,emit ,erutan ,htgnerts ,htlaew ,doG
.gnisived nwo sih fo rehtona eb ot evah dluow tI
.yllufeur dettimda eh
”.ereh ,ha …kniht em teL“
”,snaem ecneidebo enituor tahw wonk
.dnim fo ssenneek erem naht erom tub tiw ot detaler
”.snisuoc recreif sti yb dereffus
”?flesyM…“	  .aedi na mih evag thguoht tsal tahT .htaed
,llet dluoc eh sa raf sA
”?uoy wollof ot em tnaw
uoY“	  .ruf sih gnilffur yltneg
”?ecaep ni reffus ot gniyrt m’I ees uoy t’nac—uoy htiw ffo eb woN“
”…tuB“	  .rehpotsirhC tniaS fo serutaef eninac eht revo srehtaef reh fo spit eht gnihsurb
yawa dehsaw si raef sa gnidnib sti yB
,ti morf trid eht depiw ylrednet ,htrae
dna nav sti ta sralohcs dna srairf fo snoigel htiw ,ssergorp fo hcram ydaets ehT
,esiug namuh a nod ot derad llits dranyeR nehw snoisacco erar eht nO
tI“	  ”.em nethgilne ot eerf leef
”.reverof sniamer htrae eht dna“
,srats gnidaf fo aes eht otni pu gnilias ,ria eht otni flesreh dehcnual nevaR ehT	  ”.taht esU“
.debrutsidnu erutan fo tnemtnetnoc ysae eht htiw demmuh mih dnuora htworg delgnat ehT
.mih erofeb ssenkrad eht ni raeppa ot rewsna eht lliw dluoc eh fi sa
.yltnatiseh deksa eh
?nik nwo ruoy sexoftuo ohw erah eht ro ,tnepres eht ro ,flow eht fo gninnuc eht tegrof uoy oD
,dnE tuohtiW retniW ,levon tubed esohw
.derumrum dranyeR ”,keT ,uoy teem ot
.erif sti hctac ot
.secnatsmucric thgir eht ni ,flesmih rO .xof lamron a dluow erah gnideelb a fo tnecs eht ekil tsomla ni mih werd hcihw
.elzzum sih revo ti gniggard ,ecaf sih ssorca wap a depiw xof ehT ”!tinmaD“	  ”’.evarg
.derrefni ylbanosaer eb dluoc rewsna eno ylno taht gnirusne dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
ehT	  .ylmrif dias eh
srolehcab dna ,smrots ,srelevart fo nortap dedaeh-eninac—
:devired rewop tsetaerg eht si tnof siht morF“  :ekops nevaR eht
,reugav gnihtemos ,reikcirt gnihtemos rof dnim sih dehcraes xof
tah demmirb-ediw sih gnitroppus ruf tessur fo nworc eht morf ,mrof sih revo dettilf seye ydaeb stI
,dneif sselmrof siht ,dnim eht swang tI
,llef ecnanetnuoc s’dranyeR sa niaga gnilkcuhc ,desum nevaR eht
.gninetfos seye ,ylteiuq delkcuhc nevaR
…s’tahT“	  ”?gniga ni sA
,esirprus ni knilb ot xof eht koot ti emit eht nI
.stoor dna hsurb fo elgnat eht
:melborp eht tsuj
ecniS“	  ”.traeh ta xof a era uoy taht ,gnieb ruoy fo eroc tsepeed eht ot ,leef uoy ,tey dnA
hguorht ylefas mih ees ot seye enipluv sih gnitsurt
.yldalg dna ,tsinogatna eht deyalp
,detuohs eh
,eporuE ssorca lla won dna
dranyeR	  ”.uoy ot ti evig ot yppah eb dluow I neht dna—esruoc
,flesreh desopmoc drib taerg ehT
,redluohs sih no yltfos delffuhs keT .swodahs eht otni ylknalb gnirats ,sselnoitom doots
,eye s’keT thguac eh nehW
,mih ot kcab reh htiw dedulcnoc namow eht
,ylyoc delims ehS
.dnats ot gnisir ,deksa eh ”?ti si
”,feileB…“	  .riapsed fo diov eht dima efil ot derekcilf thguoht a ,gnits tfos sti gnirovas ,revlis looc eht deldarc sdap sih sA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
selddir ym rewsna uoy
”.em deen t’ndluow uoy ,did ti
flesmih niatsus ot skcirt elpmis ni gnithgiled
siH	  ”.llewd ot semot sih nihtiw gnol roF tifnu erahs retaerg eht meed dnA
”nevaR a htiW selddiR“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
ehT	  .delbmurg xof eht
.sdnah
,nosaes gnitam rieht fo gnissap eht htiw edisbus noos dluow doolb rieht ni erif ehT
.eulav gnidloh ycnerruc htiw od ot hcum gnivah ti llacer t’nod I dna“ ,dias nevaR eht
,feiht eht nopu dexif seye wolley sih ,ecilam htiw gninruB
iksaL rimisaC yb
.nediamdnah ysmulc tey gninaem-llew a gnihsinomda
?emiT“	  .gnihton delaever taht seye htiw mih gnihctaw saw ohw ,ynapmoc sih ta gnicnalg
aedi eht tsuj evah I kniht I“
dnA“	  .gninediw ylwols seye nwo sih
saznats otni meht gnicrof
,esuom a sa llams sA“
;dloc nar doolb s’xof
,gniraelc eht fo edis rehto eht ot detaerter ydaerla dah drib gnimehcs eht tub
.ylhguoroht erom divroc elttil eht gniyduts
.draehnu dna neesnu syawla yldrah saw ti dnA
namow deriah-krad ,elap a litnu srehtaef fo yrrulf a ni gnirrulb
lived fo tros emos m’I taht noitpecnocsim eht rednu gnirobal uoy era ,dranyeR“	  ”!sseug a sa tnuoc t’nseod taht—taht ,oN“
.ybsressap detnawnu fo ngis yna rof erom ecno kcehc
fI“	  .eelg sih laecnoc ylerab dluoc dranyeR
.eelf reven nac reed ehT ,em tramstuo tonnac xof ehT“
s’tahT“	  .enots ecreip dluoc taht ezag a htiw gnirats ,deksa nevaR eht
etacalp ro modgnik a eruces ton dluow enola noissap tuB ?spahrep ,noissaP
.thguob ro dlos eb sdoog dluoc yenom htiw roN
.ria thgin eht otni gnitalucitseg
,no tnew ehs ”,niw I fI
srepsihw draeh-flah ni ti fo sdrahs deggaj hctac neve dluoc eh
yreV“	  ”.eno tsal ruoy evah s’tel—taht dnim reven tuB“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ecno siht flaheb sih no edecretni thgim rehpotsirhC
.htaed liatne ylirassecen ton did egnahc tub—
si ti tub ,serutaerc fo tseitfarc eht ylirassecen ton si xof A
?tiw fo dessessop ton nerdlihc nwo ym erA“	  ”?ti t’nseoD“
fo hcaer eht edule dna
,tseW lanidraC lennahc ebuTuoY eht setarepo osla eH
,ecnamrofrep ekilecnart eht brutsid ot ton erac gnikaT
,reraen deppets ehS
.denediw krims s’dranyeR	  ”.snediam
”,srewsna owt yllacinhcet
,iksaL rimisaC yb ”nevaR a htiW selddiR“ saw sihT
,emit lanif a gniw reh fo srehtaef eht hguorht kaeb reh gniggarD ”.taht ees nac
nI“	  ”.aretec te ,sdog ,slived ,snomead ,stirips ,yef
.gnineerp nageb drib taerg ehT ”.llew
:enil yb enil elddir eht deweiver eH
,htaerb a tuo deffuh dna
,mih erofeb secap wef a ylno ,erehT
dranyeR	  .yltpurba deksa nevaR eht ”?uoy era
ehT	  .mih tfel evreser fo ecnalbmes yna
.mmH“ .rethgiarts pu doots neht
,ylthgils daeh reh dekcoc ehS
,evaus dna ,ytfarc
,flesreh desopmoc erom ecno nevaR
.yllarutan ,nwo sih naht rehto—
wonk ot dalg saw dranyeR
,llew sa siht fo erit uoy won
,ffo deliart eH ”…won dnA
,oN“	  ”—gnignahc eht dna sevael eht fo gninrut eht ma I ,yhW“
.seof gnidave dna yerp gnillef—
eutats a sa llits gniniamer
,flesmih ot delkcuhc dranyeR
.ylppa kcehc hcus on deen siht oT
skcirt ym“ ,seiromem eht revo gnikrow llits ,ylwols dias eh ”,tsrif
.trid eht ot gnipoord liat
elbuort ylno eht ;niatrec etiuq saw eh siht fO
…tsuj tI .erutan ym ni s’tI .retskcirt a m’I
,toof fo teelf os enoemos rof ,sediseB
,eid yam ekila snoitan dna nem elihw dnA
raef hsinab dluoc
.derettum nevaR eht ”,doog
,tnenitnoc eht ssorca gniredloms gnol srebme fo ekoms eht ni tfola enrob
.repsihw a ot gnippord eciov
”…ees s’tel ,thgir
tuB“	  ”.ecnatsissa fo eb yam I ,tuo ti elzzup od uoy fi tub
,regniferof a pu dleh eH
fO“	  ”.ti gnivlos pleh ruoy deen t’ndluow I ,saw melborp eht tahw wenk I fi
.thgir tsomla era uoy“
rehtar ti dnif dluow emos erus m’I“	  .ezorf xof
,dranyeR“	  ”—dluow I .sruoy wonk t’nod I diarfa m’I tub ,eman ym wonk uoy ,ydal yM“
dranyeR	  .detcejretni nevaR eht ”,yltcerroc
dum eht ni delbbauqs doG fo nem dna
,rehgrub wels norab sa
…uoy pleh lliw I ,yalpdrow fo dnof os era uoy ecniS
,stils ot slipup sih deworran nus gnittes eht nehW
.denetfos seye divroc
m’I“	  .sgnaf sih gnihsalf ,nirg a htiw dias xof eht
,ecalpnommoc emoceb dah flesti tnessid erehw dlrow a ni
,edirtsdim desuap eH
.nwo rieht fo eno sa mih democlew llits sdliw eht ,degnahc dah eh lla rof taht
.hgih liat sih dleh dna ,kcab sih denethgiarts ,erom ecno regnellahc sih ecaf ot delrihw eh ,deifsitaS .swalc sih no stnih eht ffo gnikcehc nageb neht
”,feileB“	  .laudividni yna dnoyeb raf evil ot elba tey dna
,nevaR taerg a sa tub
”.gnol rof diova tonnac nam neve taht gnihtemos
.nonnac a fo kcarc eht ta
taht eviG“ .lrans a htiw teef sih ot tpael dranyeR	  .keT dias ”,keT ,keT“	  .hpmuirt ni sgniw sti gnippalf
.evirht ro rehtiw tsum snoitibma ythgim ti yB
seirots taht wonk dluohs elpoep lla fo uoy dna—
.noilladem eht ta dehctulc dranyeR
,ylwols gnicap nageb xof ehT
.t’nsaw eh sa tsenoh sa eb dlrow eht fo skoorc eht taht saw deksa eh llA
.swaperof sih depsalc xof ehT	  .ylyrd devresbo nevaR eht
”?elbuort fo dnik
.ssarg eht gnoma sdees rof gnikcep ot denruter nevar elttil eht
,srae derruf kcalb sih dekcilf eH
debmuccus ylbativeni sgnieb gnivil lla hcihw ot ,htaed saw thguoht tsrif siH
dezilaer won eh ,wadkcaj a rof egral oot—drib ehT
”.emit tsrif eht resolc erew
roF	  .xof a rof ton yllaicepsE
I“	  ”—ylraluger deyebo eb tsum taht gnihtemoS“
,gniraelc eht hguorht tiucric a tuc eh sa duola gnikniht
oT	  .niamod evisulcxe sih regnol on saw sutats elbongi taht neve ,won tub—
retsiolc a nioj ot ffo s’eh ecnuonna ot evirra lliw floW dlo eht worromot spahreP
,dnuorg eht nopu htrof dna kcab detturts hcihw
,sdnalhgih nailotanA deggur eht fo seiromem noyclah
,nopu werd eh neve taht rewop fo ecruos A
,dlrow eht otni erif sti gnillips ,spotniatnuom tnatsid eht revo gnikaerb saw nwad wen A
ehT	  .dnah evissimsid a devaw eH
.mih ta pu gnirats nik ressel reh dnif ot ylno
sih dedlof dranyeR	  ”.klat I revenehW srae ym htiw ees I
,pup tneidebosid a ot gniooc nexiv a ekil tsomla ,dias ehs ”,dranyeR
,dranyeR	  .annodaM divroc emos ekil daeh reh gninworc noom eht htiw mrof rednels sih revo gnimool
,lardehtac etavirp nwo reh saw ti ekil tserof eht hguorht deirrac eciov s’namow
mih no tnuoc reven dluoc yeht taht saw ti
,redluohs sih no dehcrep llits keT ees ot daeh sih denrut eH
.ereh dnuora llud yllufdaerd os teg
.xof ,em romuH“	  ”?selddir eroM“
hsilpmocca eh thgim tahw
dranyeR	  ”.neewteb ni secaps eht sllif dnA
”,yllarutaN“	  ”?htiw nigeb ot elbuort ni deedni era uoy taht erus etiuq uoy era tuB“
.nirg a otni ekorb ecaf
”.trats ot erehw fo
,dna ,daeh reh detfil ehs sa tuhs dils seye s’nevaR
,keT dias ”,keT“	   .deksa eh
dranyeR	  .yltfos dekaorc nevar eht ”,keT“
.pu flesmih werd eH	  ”?uoy era tahW
,thguan snaem nworc s’hcranom a ti tuohtiW
.seye reh denepo neht ,sdnoces wef a detiaw
,detiaw dranyeR sa emit emos rof tnelis tas nevaR ehT
,deremmats eh ,kcab pets elbazis a gnikaT
,htrim rof ylerem kram a hcus evael dluoc eh fi dnA
.seye thgindim taerg reh ni gnikraps maelg yls a
.flesym esuma ot skcirt rednarg ot denrut dna
s’erehT“	  .nevar rehto yna morf tnereffid on dekool ti
,duola desum eh ”,ytinav ,ytinaV“
yaws ni dleh era seimra dna snoitagergnoC
,drawrof dehcuols
.evoba senip eht ni swadkcaj eht fo hceeps ragluv eht ot gninetsil
”,evitanretla on evah I esoppus I“	  ”.ereh
uoY“	  .tiusrup evig ton did eh nehw kcab gnilcric
.taorht sih rof degnul neht
.sbmil sih morf ssap noisnet eht fo emos
eht morf noilladem eht dehctans eH
;noitan tsniaga noitan dna esuoh tsniaga devom esuoh
,sknar eht ni gnillif ecalupop gniworg-reve na
.gnipoord liat ,srae sih deyalps xof
,flesmih ot derepsihw dranyeR ”,regnuH…“
.evarg a‘ si rewsna eht
”nevaR a htiW selddiR“   yojne esaelP
:era ew si ti revetahw“
”?uoy t’nod ,dnah reppu eht evah ot deen syawla uoy“
,elzzum sih morf sehcni ylno detser kaeb ynobe reh litnu ni gninael
,llew rednop tsum tsivihcra sihT
ehT	  ”.rewsna eht htraenu …dluoc I ylno
.dnib a fo tib a ni saw xoF eht dranyeR
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
noitcifonex yraretil fo noissucsid ot detoved yliramirp
ynnaryt fo smrof rehto lla dna ,ycneced ,ytirohtua fo ecnaifed ni efil eritne sih devil dah eh ,lla retfa rof
,nevaR eht dranyeR ton era uoy tuB
”?ylohcnaleM“	  .noitanretsnoc neve ro ,tnemesuma ,yhtapmys neeb evah dluoc tahw htiw mih gnihctaw
”…meht evlos tonnac uoy fi
.teef sih dnuora gnicnad ,swac gnikcom fo gnirts a esool tel keT
,olleH“	  .seye gniknilbnu htiw mih dehctaw—
dranyeR	  ”?hcus dellac eb dluoc ti fi ,htuoy ruoy fo rebmemer uoy od tahW
,modsiw fo trosnoc eht saw eutriv ,lla retfA
eH	  ”.taht tseggus ton did srewsna ruoY“	  .deppans xof eht
.daehrevo gnimoolb epacsrats eht ta pu gnicnalg
.drib taerg a fo mrof eht ni erom ecno flesreh gnikaolc ,denrut neht
,llacer dluoc eh selddir tluciffid tsom eht hguorht delfir dranyeR	  .seirc divroc fo gnirts a tuo gnikwauqs dna owt eht gnilcric ,redluohs sih morf dehcnual keT .ylpeed tuo dehtaerb dranyeR ”.tcerroC“
dnA“	  .noitcafsitas htiw hcir saw eciov reH
,yltneitap detiaw nevaR eht ,tiderc reh oT
noitcurtsed eht gnitivni diova ot hguone kaew tey dna nam egnellahc ot hguone gnorts
.egnarts eht ot regnarts on saw ,revewoh
.dedda nevaR eht
,trid eht ta kcab dekool
xof ,gnitsej ylerem saw I“
”,ylniatreC“	  .dias drib eht
.srehtaef kcalb fo yrrulf a ni detpure remrof eht ,kaeps dluoc eh erofeb tub
.yawa gnidirts nageb dna kcab reh denrut namow eht ,esirprus
.gniralf slirtson
”,stius gnorts ym fo eno neeb reven …sah ecneitaP“
.eciov sih gnisiar ,reh ecaf ot delrihw eh elzzum sih tfel noitseuq eht sa noos sA
etiuQ“	  .elzzum sih ssorca peerc nirg a tlef dranyeR
.gnihsilbuP sirneF morf elbaliava won si
”!moderoB“	  ?worros naht erom ssenitpme llif dluow noitome tahW
tA	  .mih tsniaga rewop elbirret reh gninrut yllanif saw
tahW“	  ”.tnemaciderp nwo ym ot ecnaveler rieht ees ot liaf I
dranyeR	  .tnemtnioppasid fo egnit a deirrac eciov reH
esuaceB…“	  .swap sih fo sdap eht otni gud swalc siH	  ”…dibrom
.reh retfa dettort eh ,gnikniht tuohtiW
.wob a fo tnih tsetniaf eht gnivig ,tah sih fo mirb eht dehcuot eH ”?gnittif rehtar eb ton taht dluow ,seil no tliub saw noitatuper eritne ym fI“
,stserc evaw tnatsid eht no gnicnad thgilyad fo remmilg lanif eht hctac ot seye sih desiar eh
,stiusrup enadnum hcus htiw derob werg I yllautneve tuB
”,od ot evah lliw siht esoppus
.rethgual suocuar fo tif a otni ekorb neht ,tnemom a mih ta derats nevaR ehT
,thgir sih ot decnalg ehS
.msacras hctac ot hguone neek eb dluow elpoep lla fo uoy thguoht I—
”?neht ,esolc saw I oS“	  ”.oN…“
s’dranyeR	  ?sngised rednarg htiw
.emalf nepo ot desool yltnecer ylno
nehW“	  ”.lla s’taht ,stiw fo hsalc derutan-doog elttil a—
.noitamina nretsew dna
,rewop taerg fo tnof a
.feileB ,moderoB ,regnuH“ .swalc sih no ffo meht dekcit dranyeR	  ”.deednI“	  .reh ot naht flesmih ot erom ,dias eh ”,selddir ehT“
”.sruoy fo teknirt elttil ynihs taht revo dnah tsum uoy“
detramstuo eb tonnac taht gnihtemoS“
.sih sa ytfarc sa dnim a rof rednit ydaer fo lluf eb ot wenk eh dlrow a
”,lareneg ni ,su naem I“
,drib taerg eht ot kcab sih denrut
”.nwo rieht fo sevil no ekat ot ycnednet a evah
mih erofeb doots ehs
.srobhgien deggel-owt sih fo robal eht no
”,dehsinif d’uoy erus eb ot detnaw I“	  ”.sseug ruoy ekaM“
.gnis ot nageb hsurht a ,ssenkrad nwaderp fo stcart eht ni erehwemoS
”,keT“	  .tah demmirb-ediw sih pota dnal ot nwod derettulf keT
,snoitats dairym fo esoht rof ytirohtua fo ecruos ,noitibma fo emalf eht ot rednit
naegeA eht fo raor eht erom ecno draeh dna
.flesmih ot yltfos derumrum xof eht
,srehtaef reh deffulf nevaR ehT	  ”.elbuort eht si ,esoppus I ,taht dnA .thguos ev’I elbuort t’nsi elbuort siht taht gnieb melborp ylno eht—ti fo tuo flesym peek dluoc reveN .elbuort rof eson a dah syawla ev’I“
”.elddir lanif ym si ereH“
”,tneitap yrev ton
neeuq a fo ecarg eht htiw deilper namow eht
sih gniworran ,derettum dranyeR
.ti fo kniht ot emoc ,detramstuo neve dna ,smrof emos ni nurtuo eb dluoc htaed tub—
,teef sih ta teknirt eht detisoped dna revo deppoh ylpmis drib eht ,esirprus
,etihw gninetsilg ni dekaolc namow denniks-elap a doots
.ylyls reh deye
,evom ton did xof eht nehW .dewac dna
,enilerohs noterB eht revo ksud otni tlem gnineve remmus diugnal eht gnihctaw
,kcab dna namow eht ot nevar eht morf decnalg
,stnih rieht tcurtsnoc ot sdrawkcab dekrow neht
.htaerb peed a tuo decrof eh ,seye sih gnisolC
:syad tseilrae sih ot kcab thguoht
,dranyeR dethgiled evah dluohs hcihw ,eroc sti ot nekahs neeb dah redro dlo
”.sseug eno sa meht tnuoc ll’I ,emag elttil ruo gniunitnoc fo ekas eht rof
roolf tserof eht ot tah s’xof eht morf derettulf keT
,grebnettiW ni tiurf ydoolb enrob yllanif dah
.nevaR eht ot nwonk eb ylerus dluow rebmemer dluoc eh gnihtyna taht gniwonk
snel yggof eht hguorht sthguoht derettacs sih decrof eh
,gnihcuols sredluohs sih ,pord ti tel neht
.sgniw taerg reh fo eno gnivaw ,dekaorc nevaR eht ”,on ,on
.daeh reh dewob nevaR
,melborp repeed a yal taht dnoyeb dnA
.meht ot dnuob reverof ,emalf rieht fo nrob rebme na era
hguoht—tcerrocni era hcihw fo htob“
sih gnileef ,erugif suoiretsym eht ot pu knuls dranyeR
.nepo gnignah htuom ,desuap xof eht ereh tuB ”—uoy od tahW“
.ecalos railucep fo egnit a ti htiw thguorb pirg nori s’nam fo hcaer eht dnoyeb selcyc fo thguoht eht dna
”.neht ,eno tsrif ruoy raeh s’tel ,lleW“
,rof mih no tnuoc dluoc srehto gniht eno saw ereht fI
:worros ni detiforp rettal eht ni deniag reveohw dna
.ti gniniag diova ot wonk dluow modsiw fo ecnuo na htiw enoyna ,yllarutan
,kwah a sa teelf sA
dnA“	  ”.kees I ecivda eht em evig nrut ni llahs uoy neht—
:taorht sih deraelc eH ”!ahA“
.rethgual gniwac suocuar fo tif a otni gnikaerb erofeb regnol tnemom a mih ta derats ylpmis nevaR ehT	  ”.laed riaf a yldrah s’taht—s’tahT“
,kcen sih dnuora gnuh taht—
,mrof ywodahs reh tuo ekam regnol on dluoc eh litnu derats dranyeR
yltcerroc—selddir ruoy rewsna I fI :esruoc fo ,esruoc fO“ .sdnah sih desiar
,pmuts delrang a no tas
.flesti emoR fo traeh eht ot modnetsirhC fo sredrob eht fo sdleifelttab eht morf dna
.nroh s’retnuh eht fo tsrub eht ta sekaseman deggel-ruof sih fo eno fo raef eht wenk eh ,tnemom a rof
”,elbuort fo tib a ni eb ot mees I“
,raef ot etoditna nA
,ekahs ton dluoc eh eson esohw dnuoh a dellacer eH
”.uoy knahT“ .derettum dranyeR ”,mmH“
.sevael fo eltsur eht otni gnidlem
,keehc sih ot dnah gnitrofmoc a dehcuot ehS
tahW“	  .tnetsisni erom werg keT
dranyeR	  .enog saw drib eht
.lluks sih otni degnulp eb ot ydaer reggad a ekil desiop
dranyeR ,hself nevig yrots a era
,gniw evissam a tuo dehcterts ehS
,yawa tfird ezag sih tel eH ”.esnes sekam
”,ti deyojne etiuq I ,htrow s’ti tahw
.yad fo gnimoc eht htiw mid gniworg flesti
,delbmur nevaR eht
namuh denniks-elap a sa ton
sA“	  ”.niagrab ruo fo dne ruoy dlehpu uoy emit s’ti—nevaR ,selddir ruoy devlos ev’I ,woN“
ehT	  ”.erutan gnitsurt a retsof yltcaxe t’nseod ti ,evah I sevil eht devil ev’uoy
.traeh sih ot dnah a gnipsalc ,denoorc dranyeR
,god a fo evitcepsrep eht morf dlot yrots lavivrus citpylacopa-tsop a
”?sdnal ffo-raf morf swen terces repsihw ot emoC“
nehW	  .kcirt doog a etaicerppa did syawla eH
dranyeR	  .emit driht a ria eht otni gnipael
ehT	  ”.tiefrof eb lliw efil ruoY…“
nac tI .em romuh ,esaelP“
.eciov sih desiar neht ,deilper xof eht
,emoh dellac gnol dah xof eht dnal eht revo emoc dah egnahc fo tros rednarg a ,etal fo ,tey
tahW“	  ”.enim naht esac ruoy ni os eroM .tsomlA
I“	  ”.llew sa selddir ym fo eerht rewsna ot evah uoy tuB .eniF…“
I“	  .ecnelis eht kaerb ot devom yllanif eh nehw neve
:uoy rof noitisoporp a evah I