,senyeK notliM ni pots tsrif sti sdrawot ,yelhctelB hguorht yaw sti edam dah niart eht emit eht yB
,rehtegot sgnignoleb ruoy teG
.sehciwdnas deirf gge dna nocab owt s'taht ,thgirlA"
- nottiD .L samohT" daer hcihw
,dias droffilC ".sakuL"
,ttoillE m'I" .dias xof ehT ".eman
,ezalb a tuo gnittup rof serudecorp erif tcaxe eht fo erawa ton saw sakuL
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sakuL ta dekrab droffilC
esac egaggul sih ni dah eh ,yllanoitiddA
.elpoep fo gnorht eht otni deraeppasid xof eht sa gnihctaw
.wap dehctertstuo eht morf repap fo eceip eht koot dna deddon sakuL
,delbmurg eH "!hsuhS" .dias ehS
,sehcaoc yvruc ylthgils owt gnissap neht
,ssergorp ot htap eht no deyortsed
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.elubitsev eht ni metsys AP eht revo
,dnim ni siht htiW
.wogsalG ot htron snur ro notsuE ot snruter ti nehw niart siht no kooc ot deen lliw eH"
,detnurg droffilC ".niaga
"!yllort kcans eht ot emoclew dna ydobyreve gninrom dooG“
.yllort ytekcir rehtar ,llams a sdrawot daeh sih gninrut
.niaga nehctik eht otni tsrub droffilC
.ecnart sih fo tuo pans ot sakuL gnisuac
,ssenihtrow lacirtcele ot nwod saw ti ereh morF
,deirc mussop ehT "!kcuf hO"
,denaelc neeb dah nehctik eht ,gnol erofeB
,dnuora denrut sakuL
,pot rab eht no ti gnicalp dna norpa eht gnikat
.elsilraC ro wogsalG ees uoy litnu tiaw
.droffilC ta pu thgiarts gniralg ,deworruf worB
.kle eht yb deppots saw tub
.yaw cificeps a deraperp eb ot dah hciwdnas a
,nekatrevo gnieb ro yaw rehto eht yb gnissap
.ylbatrofmoc krow ot nosrep eno rof hguone gib yllaer ylno dna
,teef sih ot teg ot meht esu ot deirt eh sa derepmihw eH
,ni emoc lliw no krow nac uoy niart txen eht erofeb kaerb ruoh flah a eb ll'erehT"
.kaeps ot detrats eh sa oidar dlo na ekil delkcarc eciov siH
.reets ot drah gniht eht gnikam
,acsecnarF dna droffilC neewteb dekool sakuL
,repap nehctik emos debbarg enipluv ehT .delbmum xof ehT ".sdnah
dah sregnessap eht unem emas eht fo ypoc a dna
.eldniwd ot demees srebmun regnessap eht sa
,nehctik eht fo tuo devom dna aremac sih debbarg mussop eht
tekcop rezalb tius sih ot deppilc egdab eman ytiCretnI elttil a dah eh
.eman ruoy hctac did reven I"
"?ekil er'yeht tahw wonk I lliw woh
.ffo klaw ot detrats dna
...I" .deplug mussop ehT .dias ttoillE ".yademos
,tset tsrif sih no krap eht fo tuo ti kconk ot neeK
,pu dekcap sgnignoleb sih htiW
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.delbmessa hciwdnas eht dah dna stneidergni eht lla gnikooc dehsinif dah sakuL
.sakuL nihtiw niaga flesti eldnik ot detrats tnemeticxe fo erif taht ,mroftalp eht no ecnO
,xof eht gnicaf riahc eht ni taes a koot os
.esrow aesuan ’sakuL ekam ot deunitnoc ria eht ni gnuh taht ekoms ehT
.sdnah degadnab sih desiar mussop eht
.depoh I yaw eht tuo dennalp t'nsah
.ti nopu nettirw redro eht htiw repap eulb fo eceip llams a gnidloh
.ffo denaelc yltsom neeb dah skram nrub eht dna
.yrruh ’sakuL erahs ton did meht neewteb srood ehT
,nnamrebod a ot degnoleb eciov ehT
.ti pots ot dnuora ydoboN
,seno dlo ytekcir eht ,sniart wen gnimaelg eht
,dlrow eht tuoba gniht eht s'tahT .won rof ,lleW"
dnabsuh sih morf tfig gnitrap a sa nevig saw eh eno
,s'droffilC ,eciov eht saW ".desivda
,edis eno ot sgniht denrub gnittup
.yawa aremac sih gnittup ,daeh sih koohs sakuL
.sdnah sih dedlocs slortnoc eht sa kcab delbmuts dna depley sakuL
,renid ro tnaruatser teerts lamron a fo snehctik eht ot derapmoc cipocsorcim saw tI
,sniart eht fo emos gnirewop elbac lacirtcele eht deirrac hcihw
fo aingisni rettel latipac eht dna edis eht nwod epirts egnaro elttil
,nehctik eht pu naelc ot detrats yeht dna
.dne raf eht ta evitomocol yxob dna duol ,egral a dna
.ssorca dekool sacuL
retiusruf dna naicisum
"?ekil s'taht esoppus ay’d tahW“
.sdnah ruoy no emit ssecxe tog ev'uoy ees I"
.sredro txen eht rof deraperp dna sdnah sih dehsaw
,ecaf sih no hsulf der kciht a
.niaga noitom deniag niart eht sa
.mih ecaf ot ylprahs gninrut lla sregnessap eht
.nirg a htiw pu kcab dekool mussop ehT .dekrab eH
.evren sih gnisol saw eh erawa ,htaerb peed a koot sakuL
,teef sih sdrawot sakuL depleh enoemos ,tsal tA ".taht
.meht neewteb elbat eht
.pot rab eht no tas llits norpa sih gniees
”emitefiL a fo ediR“
,mroftalp eht pu yaw sih ekam d'eh neht dna
,egrem dna elgnim skcart dehctaw eH
snwot detsen llams emoceb dah sdleif nepo egral ehT
notsuE nodnoL fo steliot eht ni ton dna ,emoh ta demoorg evah dluohs eno spahrep hguoht
.htaerb a koot dna xof eht ta ylprahs derats kle ehT .deksa xof ehT
.denrub lla yeht elihw yb dnats ot gniog t’nsaw eh tub
.kooc yawliar a sa boj a tog I yhw s'tI" .dias eH ".dleifnE
htaerb peed a koot eH
,tnelis deniamer mussop ehT
.deppans mussop ehT
,sleehw retsac no dna thgil saw yllort ehT
,sdrawot yaw rieht edam elpoep hcihw
.flesmih desopmoc sakuL sa
.decitonnu enog ton dah
”.msaisuhtne ruoy rof llik d’I doG“
".hguolS naht retteb ylerab s'tI“
,rood eht ta neht dna
,eldnah rood eht ot nwod dehcaer eh erofeb
,aremac paehc yrev a
,delkcuhc eH ".melborp on
.sthgis eht ees og ot tnaW
ngised ni seno ssalc tsrif owt eht ekil erom sehcaoc ssalC dradnatS eht fo tser eht
,tekcaj tius eht fo tekcop renroc pot eht ot deppilc egdab ssarb llams a no desucof seye s'sakuL .dekwauqs eH ".uoy
snoitcnuj fo ssam eht ereh morf ees ot elba
,erutats ni erauqs dna ralugnA
,murdlod tsedom a tsrif ta saw swodniw fo kcal s'nehctik ehT
,og uoy erofeb dna ,hO"
.kcolc gnikcit eht fo erawa
.tol a ereh emoc elpoep rednow on ...roC"
.erofeb yreneerg hcus nees reven d'eH
”.efil ym lla nodnoL fo sparcs emas eht dnuora gnittis fo kciS
ti gnillac ot noitasinredom ehT
;raer eht ta hcaoc bac eht fo ngised eht dehctam gnola elcihev htruof ehT
,dat a daeh sih fo kcab eht gnibbur
.nehctik eht edistuo morf llac a saw ".sehciwdnas
.egairrac eht fo tser eht yb derahs ton saw msaisuhtne ecnamrofrep sih gnisilaer ,dellats sakuL
dna wodniw eht nwod dellup eH
niaga aremac sih pu koot mussop ehT
.hcaoc eht fo pot eht gnola devom ti sa eno wolley eht decalper hcihw epirts der eht yb decnedive
,deksa sakuL ”?hguolS"
,retnuoc rab eht ot devom yeht ,ecneH
.deppots neht gnilkcarc ehT ".degamad
,mussop eht ot deined gnieb yks eznorb siht fo weiv a
,tahw ni pots a ot emac niart eht sA
,draoba kcab ecnO
:metsys sserdda cilbup s’noitats eht revo tnemecnuonna na yb deppots saw tub
,tnatropmi erew snoisserpmi tsriF
nwod gnillup ,rood egairrac eht sdrawot devom sakuL
.niaga em tnioppasid t'nod won ,dooG"
,hcum gnihtemos fo trats eht ylno ,yllaer saw
.tnemhsinup sih htiw enola mussop eht gnivael
.sresuort kcalb dna tavarc der htiw trihs etihw a dalc
.sunimret rieht ot lavirra gnidnepmi rieht gnillangis
.slevart sih tnemucod ot
.dnuopmoc ot repmet sih desuac ylno niart eht hguorht yllort eht ediug ot stroffe s’sakuL
.rac teffub eht sdrawot niart eht pu gnitlob dna teef sih ot gnilbmarcs
.hguone eb ot ylekilnu saw sdnuop fo elpuoc a tub
.nwod ti dloh ot gniog t'nsaw rehsiugnitxe eht demees ti dna
,gnirednaem saw eh erawa saw eH
.deredro droffilC ".woN"
.teertS weN ta ecivres fo tuo niart siht ekat ot gniog er'yeht ,thgirlA"
.eromyna norpa taht gnisu eb t'now uoy
yltnacifingis decuder erew hcaoc txen eht ni sgniht gnilles rof snoitpo sih dnif ot deyamsid saw eH
.mih erofeb srebmem ffats eht fo rehtien saw ti hguoht
taeh eht morf niaga decniw eH
,si taht tahw wonk neve t’nod I ,stiucsib ,sexob eciuj ,sehciwdnas tog ev’eW“
.setunim 01 tuoba ni hguorht eb dluohs ew
”emitefiL a fo ediR“   :yojne esaelP
.sregnessap ssalC tsriF rof erew yeht taht gnitacidni
.aesuan fo tib a ni tes ot detrats dah gniyaws tfos s'hcaoc eht
,niart eht fo htgnel eht pu dekool dna desuap sakuL
.ecnesba s’droffilC gniton
.wodniw eht fo tuo kool ot gninrut
.nehctik eht otni yaw sih gnikam erofeb
.desivda eb sremotsuC"
,elbmurg ot deunitnoc naws ehT ".yssalc
.siht fo lla fo erutnevda eht no ecsinimer ot nageb sakuL ,os did eh sA
.ytterp saw ti ssendooG
,eveels sih htiw raet a epiw ot dehctiwt
.eriuqse ,fehc tnemecalper a deen ll'I fi wonk ot deen I
"?kooc llits uoy naC"
.dias eh ".ecivres fo tuo gniht siht ekat yeht fi sdnepeD" .deddon droffilC
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,kle eht morf eralg a gninrae
.mih demrofni kle ehT ".eromyna
.smroftalp suonrevac eht otno nwod spmar erew ereht morf dna
.niaga ecno nehctik eht ot kcab devom dna egaggab sih ni kcab aremac eht tup mussop eht
.flesti noitats eht ssorca ralucidneprep detcurtsnoc egdirb krownori tsav a derutaef ybguR
,yawrood egairrac eht ni doots acsecnarF gniciton
,yaw siht lla emoc t’ndah eH
,dat a lruc pil rewol sih tlef eH
,noitats lanoitanretnI mahgnimriB wen rehtar eht hguorht gnihsur niart eht ,dias kle ehT ".setunim
,sdnah denrub s'sakuL dnuora segadnab ekil ti depparw neht dna ti tew
.spil sih morf deppird egar s'droffilC
.sdradnats eseht rof koobediug a htiw mih dedivorp dna
.derots erew slisnetu dna stneidergni eht lla erehw yfitnedi ot meht no slebal dah sdraobpuc dna sward eht taht dna
.teiuq ylbanosaer llits hguoht
.niaga pu taeh ot detrats doolb s’sakuL
dednettanu nehctik eht evael ot emit hguonE“ .dias eH ".sdnah
.eno rehto yna ro niart siht ni kooc
"…wonk’y ,tub ttim ruoy ekahs dluow I"
,taht mih ot desserts neeb dah ti hguoht
,nageb kle ehT ",esac hcihw nI"
”,wonk'y ,senyeK notliM ni er'uoY"
,dnuorgrednu dils ti sa tneidarg a nwod esae ot nageb dna lwarc a ot dewols niart ehT
,os did eh sa dnA
.setunim wef tsrif eht nihtiw edisa dekconk eb ot tsuj
.niaga elpoep otni gnipmub pu dne syawla uoy
.neeb reve d'eh erehwyna morf yawa selim saw eH
.flaheb sih no seuqehc esoht hsac dluoc sracs sih dna
,noitats eht pu edam hcihw mroftalp dnalsi lartnec eht ssorca gninnaps
.sdnaldiM eht rof dedaeh dna
.rehtegot mussop eht dna xof eht gnivael
;noitats teertS weN mahgnimriB fo spit mroftalp gnidurtorp eht dekaos thgilnus duorp sihT
,thgirlA" .deddon sakuL ".noitcerid
nehctik eht eruces ot devom mussop ehT
resiurb nodnoL htuos hguor fo erutxim a eciov sih ,dellac eH ".ereh
,gninnalp drawrof fo tops a nI
.dednetni eh tahw t’nsaw siht
dnif nac uoY .lla rof eno
.ees uoy ,ybguR morF
,sselhceeps ,daed deppots sakuL ".yrros m'I"
slevart sih ni taht depoh eH
boh eht no degar llits erif ehT
,steltuo doof dna spohs ynam desuoh hcihw rodirroc latnoziroh niht a hguorht del smroftalp eht ot etuor eht
"ssalc dnoces" ton "ssalc dradnats"
”…yad dleif gnikcuf a evah ll’I“ "...ll’I
,nehctik egral eht saw
,tnemevom yllort eht fo deeps eht dehctam meht detarepo taht setalp erusserp eht ,esroW
.elzzum sih ssorca deraems nirg a
.sessap niart rehtona elihw setunim 5 rof dnats a ta eb lliw niart siht ,desivda eb sregnessaP"
tub noitacol wen a dnuora gnikool og ot tnemeticxe fo hctiwt eht dah llits eH
".uoy teem ot desaelp
,sserdda cilbup eht ot kcab devom dna desolc rood eht demmals droffilC
detrap srood fo tes tsal eht ,yllaniF
,erofeb noitats niart a ni neeb reven d'eh ,boj eht tog d'eh litnu ,dlot eb hturT
edis eht ot sleeh tius sserd etalucammi sih denrut eH
,thgila llew saw won yb nehctik ehT
”.serutnevda no ffo naws dna
,evitomocol eht htiw detniauqca retteb teg ot derised sakuL elihW
noitats eht no elpoep wef eht yb gnigduJ
.deudbus msaisuhtne dna prahs daeh sih tpek tnemtaertsim fo gnits taht dna sdnah sih ni niap eht
.mih ta kcab thgir gnikool droffilC
.gnidir won saw sakuL dnik eht ekil ssergorp
.pot no pu tliub dah taht staf taem eht morf ezalba
.xof eht morf guh a yb detpurretni saw ecnart siH
,elzzum sih fo pot eht dnuora tuo dekop hcihw hteet raer owt sih gniton
?ti ekat I ,snoitaler cilbuP"
.krow ti ekam ot neek saw mussop eht tub
,ybguR fo nwot eht dna erihskciwraW ot
.dleifnE si neeb reve ev'I tsehtruf ,notxirB ni desiar dna nrob ,yllaer toN"
.desuap mussop ehT
.tsugsid fo gnirettulps lareneg a otni nwod gniyd regna fo erif eht
.mroftalp eht no pahc evitisiuqni eht erew uoy eveileb od I ,ereht olleh ,hO"
,semalf eht revo ti werht dna ti debbarg eh ,gnitatiseh tuohtiW
msibuc gnitnelernu rieht ni dlob dna duorp
,esae ot nageb sdnah sih fo gninrub eht sA
,kle eht yfsitas ot gninrae eb ot desoppus saw eh hcum woh wonk t'ndid eH
.denrub sdnah siH
,no gniniamer llirg eht tuoba yllatnemadnuf deergasid dah mussop eht ,gniniart eht gniruD
.etummoc ym si siht ,seY" .deksa sakuL
ti no edahs gnitsac krownori eht htiw mroftalp eht fo evruc gnol eht ni gnitteg
.revo ekat stekram eht ni ecneirepxe sih tel sakuL
,dnah ni gab dna kcen sih dnuora aremac sih htiw ,sakuL
.nehctik eht morf gniruop ekoms kcihT
.ytic eht gnideef sniev dna seiretra
.mih erofeb doots nehctik eht dna mih neewteb srood fo tes lanif dna htfif eht sa delworg eH "!nom'c ,nom'C" .gninrub llems dluoc eh ,resolc tog eh sA
,daerb dna taem rof rehto eht ,stcudorp yriad rof saw llirg eno taht deton eH
.yssalc dna deifingid kool ot desoppus si liaR hsitirB ...doG doog
.epacsdnal talf eht gnireuqnoc
.niaga eldniker ot nageb erutnevda fo erif eht
.deddon mussop ehT .droffilC sa
”.dedaj uoy ekam ot sdnet ,tuo yad ,ni yad skcumhcs eciffo knurd ,tnagorra htiw gnilaeD
,god.ecioveht ta
.dnal eht revo depard erutan fo steknalb ekil gnillor
.mrof dna ssentaen fo kcal a eciton dluoc eh
srewot dna serips ni sthgiL
”…dna aloc fo selttob
.ylsuovren delkcuhc xof ehT ".ssefnoc
.eno rof lla dna ,lla rof eno
levart dluoc eno erehw tuoba noitamrofni gnireffo dna stekcit gnilles sksoik gnimaelG
.tfihs tsrif evisnetni na etapicitna t’ndid eh
sevlesmeht gnoma gniklat ro wodniw eht fo tuo gnikool ot denruter tser eht hguoht
.mih ta kcab gnikool nehctik eht fo yawrood eht ni doots acsecnarF dna droffilC ees ot ylno
,oot gnitingi ti pots ot raelc norpa eht deggut neht dna
,hteet esoht ,riah fo enam tahT"
.flesti noitats eht ta tuo dereep
ffats niart fo rebmem rehtona yb pu nekat noos saw nehctik eht ot txen ksed ehT
neht dna gnitaes ssalc tsrif eht fo erom gnitrops
,tug eht ot eenk eht debme neht
,selgnatcer etercnoc yerg tnecifingam ,tsav fo elpmet a nopu llef seye s’sakuL
.scitna sih ot noitpecxe ekat ot gniog saw enoemos ecnahc dilos a saw ereht taht dna
.xof eht ot yllacitsacras delrans eH ".eriuqse
,ees dluoc eye eht sa raf sa rof sllih dna seert dna sdleiF
.delbmurg acsecnarF
.niaga evom ot nageb niart eht sa daeh reh sdrawot gnivom wap
seriw elttil fo sderdnuh eht ot
rehtona eno ta deralg moor eht fo nem desserd tsetrams owt ehT
.mih ta revo gnikool nnamrebod eht htiw
.esruocnoc noitats delledomer ylwen eht otno dna steliot eht fo tuo deklaw eH
.thgis ni saw ydobon esiwrehto hguoht ,dedlof smra
.ni flesmih dnuof won eh dlrow ycnaf eht ta tnemeticxe lufeelg eht dna
"!fehc eht era uoY"
.naelc epiw a sgniht gnivig dna
.yllaer boj eht koot I yhw s’tI“ .dehgis mussop ehT
elip a ni decalp doof deniur dna sexob denrub eht lla htiw
daeh sih koohs sakuL
,ecnatsid eht otni ffo gnidaerps
.staes elsia gnicaf-drawrof eht fo eno ni gnittis taoctsiaw a dna trihs etihw a ni xof der a ees ot dnuora denrut mussop ehT ".mroftalp
.tius kcalb etalucammi na ni
,uoy llet I tahw od ot gniog uoy erA“
.dnah sih ni thgit-eciv dehctulc
aremac eht no serutcip detimil dah eh taht erawa saw eH
”.teg I tahw si siht dna sregrub emos pilf ot detnaw tsuj I ,tsirhC gnikcuF“
.nocixel s'kle eht nihtiw ton saw
,retirw a sa edart sih seilp ohw
"?si ohw neht ,fehc eht ton er'uoy fi ,lleW"
.egairrac eht fo ertnec eht morf gnimoc dnuos gnilkcarc duol a saw erehT
,yenom eht ,ecnahc eht dah reven I .yllaer ton ,oN“
neht saw taht tub
,notsuE ni naws eht ekil ,taht gniton
til ylmid rehtar saw ecapskrow siH
.won ni dellup tsuj ,yrtnevoC"
.notsuE tfel ecivres
lufraF lacsaP yb
.dat a gniggas waj ,derettum eh "...taht
,seciohc sih fo sseldrager dehsinup eb ot ylekil saw eh taht desilaer tub
,elubitsev eht ni metsys sserdda cilbup eht dna
...slaem eht gnikooc star teerts evah yeht won dna
enilfoor eht ssorca epirts wolley kciht ,thgirb a htiw tub ,redlo
.slevart sih no saw eh erehw fo kcart peek dluoc eh os
,erutcip eht dna snoitaerc sih neewteb dekool eh sA
no sgniht tup ot setalp detrossa
.egap ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,teertS weN ot setunim 02 ylno s'tI"
swodniw gnidils htiw srood gninepo-launam eht deton eH .draoba debmilc dna rac teffub eht ot rood eht denepo mussop ehT
.erow eh norpa dna trihs trams eht ni tahwemos dehsinimid ezis sih
,draoba eb ydaerla ot demees elpoep wef woh dna
,niart eht gnola pu devom mussop ehT
doof fo noitatneserp citehtsea eht tuoba selur evisnetxe dedulcni nevig neeb dah sakuL gniniart detimil ehT
.ylsuorogiv deddon eH
.ssalc tsrif otni kcab gniklaw dna gninrut neht
.skcol lanac ekil tlef neewteb devom mussop eht egairrac hcaE
.sgniht sih rehtag ot gnitrats
.won saw siht dna
"?uoy evah ,hcum tuo tog t'nevah uoY"
.mroftalp eht otno deppets dna rood eht nepo gnuws
bew eht no seirots erom
.retnuoc eht pota meht decalp dna nehctik eht morf tuo deppets sakuL ,enod ecnO
,tseisub eht saw evres ot dah mussop eht sehcaoc evif eht fo tsrif ehT
,tnorf eht ot resolc devom eh sA
”?niart siht fo ffo uoy kcik ot evah ot gniog I ma ro
.neht tsafkaerb ym tog tsuj I gniht doog a s’ti ,lleW“
.erans a ni mussop a ekil ti gnippart
ssentrams dna tiftuo sih no drah os dekrow
doof teerts ni edart yrekooc sih deilp d’eH
.deilppa erew yeht sa dat a gnirepmihw rettal eht
,evoba ytic eht fo weiv eht ,erutcetihcra bals etercnoc eht ,seriw eht
dehsiugnitxe neeb sah tI
,retnuoc eht revo detluav mussop eht dna
.yademos niaga uoy ees ll'I epoh I .efas eB"
,mih ta desumeb kool ot deunitnoc acsecnarF
niaga evom ot detrats niart eht sa ecnelis ot llef owt ehT
.uoy fo etats eht ta kool snevaeh dooG"
,pots a ot emac niart eht sA
,gnihtyna yas dluoc mussop eht erofeB
"?pirt taht rof sbmulp dna yenoh htiw kcud tsaor a redro ot elbail enoemos si
,dnuora mrow dluow sniart elttil tnereffiD
”.emit doog a yllaer ton s'won ,thgif teerts a eerefer ot evol d'I elihW
,stih wef a ekat dluoc ohw nam fo dnik eht ylraelc saw eh tuB
,erugif detius eht ta kcab thgir gnikool tsuj
,erihsnotpmahtroN dna erihsmahgnikcuB fo syellav eht hguorht senyeK notliM morf deunitnoc yenruoj s’mussop ehT
”.won erofeb gnirutnevda og ot ytiliba eht
.teef sih fo tuo pord ot demees luos s'sakuL
.emoh morf raf ,raf ecalp a fo mroftalp eht otno dna niart eht fo tuo deppets
.wodniw eht tsap yb og dlrow eht gnihctaw dna ti no gninael
yrtnevoC ni stnemom wef a rof gnisuap eb lliw ew tub
,ylpmil dat a os gniod sakuL
.flesti notsuE ekil nahtaivel a ton ylniatrec
.ti rehtoms ot gnihtemos dedeen eH
,emoc dah niart eht erehw sdrawot nwod erutcip a teg ot denrut neht dna
.ereh sehciwdnas eht toG"
,hguone kcab dehsup saw erif eht ecnO
.yelgnaL sgniK raen erihsdroftreH fo sllih eht ta swodniw eht fo tuo weiv gniretaw-eye na sakuL gnivig
.niaga nehctik eht retne-er dluoc sakuL erehw tniop eht ot nwod semalf eht gnitteg boj dilos ylriaf a did rehsiugnitxe ehT
.rednop ot nageb xof eht dna norpa sih gnitacsifnoc kle eht denialpxe sakuL ".depoh
emitefil a fo edir eht ekil tlef dah tahw
.ekat-elbuod a dah enipluv ehT .deksa eH
,noitcelfer sih ta dekool eh sA
,raeppasid dna raeppa
,deffatsnu yltnerruc saw flesti rab ehT
.sdnah ruoy ta kool ,yemilB"
.ruf sih ni sracs tniaf eht dna
,foor a fo bals etercnoc sselerutaef dna evissam eht pu gnidloh srallip gnisimorpmocnu eht ot
,skramdnal cihtilonom sa doots yehT
.roolf delit eht revo gnilkraps dna gnilkniwt
,tops cinecs dna gniticxe ,wen a saw
,eciov a emac ".sknahT"
,droftaW ot ti edam dah niart eht emit eht yB
."semaJ .tS droffilC" daer hcihw
.taeh eht ffo denrut dna htrof deppets eh
,kcab eht ta reliart egaggul gnivird eht gnissap tsrif
.kaeuqs citehtap a htiw dna ylwols detrap yehT
,tnorf eht sdrawot gnicaf niart eht fo htgnel eht pu tohs eno koot eh
.gnola hcaoc txen eht rof devom eh sa raj eht dnuora gninnips snioc eht ta dekool sakuL
nisab eht morf retaw eht htiw tellum sih kcab dekcils sakuL
,sehciwdnas eht fo eno yub dna mih ytip ot demees takreem a ,yllautnevE
”?taht rof ,won thgir
72:50 eht ,5 tsap flah ta dna
”?erofeb sgel ruoy dehcterts reven uoY“
.gninrom evarb a fo thgil eulb latsyrc thgirb eht otni niaga tuo gnippop dna
”.yb og sdleif eht dna seert eht dna sllih eht gniees ,yad yreve siht ekil levart ot evol d'I" .deilper xof ehT ".ees
.eussit a debbarg dna tiftuo eht derebmemer neht
tis ot desu sgnirrae sih erehw sebol rae sih ni seloh eht
.fo duorp tsom saw eh taht tiftuo sih saw ti
,acsecnarF detcurtsni kle ehT ".em wollof ,uoY"
,deppiuq eH ",lufituaeB
.tsetal eht ta lanoitanretnI mahgnimriB yb uoy ot kcab troper ll'I dna pu siht naelC"
.no dna ffo nettog dah elpoep ynam taht gniton ,dnuora dekool eH
.pot eht no erutcurts ekil-xob egral a rednu neddih tser eht
.cigam fo bew dettonk a tsuj saw
,reetyksuH yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
,aera gnitiaw egral eht morF
,yllort eht pu ekat ot nehctik eht tfel dna deddon eH
,sgnidnuorrus wen sih tnemucod ot detrats dna
."reciffO gnitarepO feihC ytiCretnI
.noitats notsuE tsav eht fo mroftalp htneetfif eht morf traped ot deludehcs saw dna kcolc'o neves dnuora ta evirra ot deludehcs ,teertS weN mahgnimriB ot ecivres 72:50 eht saw niart s'sakuL
.teertS weN mahgnimriB otni lavirra gnidnepmi rieht fo sregnessap eht gnimrofni
,tas niart eht ,erehT
.mih rof gnitiaw doots acsecnarF gniees
.retnuoc eht fo tnorf eht ot dnuora gnivom
.ffats gniretac ytiCretnI s'liaR hsitirB fo mrofinu eht erob won erugif sih ,oN
,gniticxe sdnuos mahgnimriB knihT
,sllirg owt deniatnoc osla nehctik ehT
egairrac eht fo flah nrehtron eht pu gnikat
.selbahsirep detrossa dna staem ,seseehc gniniatnoc ,egdirf llams a saw erehT
.wodniw eht fo tuo daeh sih dereep
,dias mussop ehT ".od lliw
,trap ylwols ot srood eht rof etalp erusserp eht no pots
.tnempiuqe eht htiw detniauqca teg ot detrats dna
.kniht flesmih raeh ot redrah ti gnikam ,reduol werg evitomocol eht fo dnuos eht
”?thgir ,gniddik eb ot tog ev’uoY“
"?erofeb mahgnimriB ot neeb uoy evaH"
,mrof cibuc dna tuons ytniop ralugna sti htiw
.staes eht fo eno morf eciov a yb tsal ta deppots saw ssergorp drawno 'sakuL
.retnuoc eht dniheb nnamrebod eht fo ecaf eht no kool delzzup eht yb tnemom a rof detlah saw hguoht
ll'I neht ,fehc eht llits m'I fI“ .delbmum sakuL
.ti was eh ,yllaniF
.dias mussop ehT ".sakuL"
.no denrut llits ylbaborp erew srekooc eht
,dekrims acsecnarF
"?uoy did ,boh eht ffo nrut mih tel t'ndid uoY"
,dehctaw gnieb saw eh fi ees ot rood eht ot kcab dekool sakuL
,kcab gnippets neht dna mussop eht dnuora morf smra sih gnipparwnu ,dias xof ehT ".niaga
.rood eht ni doots llits kle eht ,esuap a saw erehT
.noitcerid thgir eht ni uoy tniop dluohs yeht ,ytriht-neves ta eciffo noitats eht ot troper uoy fi
.etuor eht no sevitomocol rehto eht fo emos dna
,lennut krad gnol a hguorht
.mroftalp eht otno nwod yaw sih edam dna
,nehctik eht ni neeb dah ydobon fI
ti htiw detniauqca retteb teg ot elba eb thgim eh
.gninrom eht fo sruoh llams eht ni
,kle eht ot tuo ti gnidloh dna daeh sih revo norpa eht gniggut dna gnihgis erofeb
,ylduol decnuonna sakuL
.htaerb sih rednu ylteiuq gnitnurg
.tekcop sih fo tuo ediug eht dellup dna retnuoc eht no nwod redro eht decalp eh
.mih no seye lla dah eh taht erawa emaceb sakuL
.srekooc eht otno rehsiugnitxe eht dehsaelnu eH
"?degamad nehctik eht sI"
,em gnirif er’uoY“ .delworg eH
,hcum oot kcul sih yrt ot gnitnaw toN
,srekooc eht no gniyl sexob wef a
.degamad neeb sah gnihton taht erusne ot
.rac teffub eht otni kcab derebmalc dna sleeh sih no denrut eh
,nehctik eht ni deniamer eh gnidivorp
htolc ssalc elddim-reppu emas eht morf tuc ylgnimeeS
spam dna selbatemit ,stelhpmap wef a pu kcip ot emit emos gnikat
dna eno rof lla ,reetyksuH yb uoy rof daer ,lufraF lacsaP yb
.si ydobyna kniht t'nod I"
.erofeb dekool reve d'eh naht retrams saw tI
.nehctik eht otni kcab yaw sih edam dna deddon sakuL
.ti fo esnes ekam t'ndluoc eh ,edis ot edis morf deyaws egairrac eht sa tub
,elsia eht nwod tnirps d'eH .mih fo ton tub
,taht esilaer ot eye s'sakuL ot raet a thguorb ti
gab sih derots eH
.ecaf sih tsniaga hsur ria eht gnileef dna wodniw eht
.erutcip a deppans
.taht yas d'uoy gnipoh saw I"
erutnevda s'sakuL ,revewoH
.noitartsurf ni delbmurg sakuL
.sgnilrad ,sgnilraD"
.eussi na eb t’ndluow ti
.dnuof reven eh hcihw nottub odnu lacigam a rof elbmarcs ot demees eh sa sdrow sih fo kcart gnisol
"won ma I tahw s'taht sseug I ,haey neht ,snoitaler cilbup sa stnuoc stun fo sexob tpircsed-non dna sehciwdnas ffo gninwap fi ,lleW"
.deilper sakuL ".fehc eht ksA"
"?he ,sehciwdnas wef a golf t'nac ytisoiruc ruoy fi ees dna ssalc dnoces hguorht yllort taht ekaT"
.retsiger ot mees t’ndid ehs eno
.draob no sregnessap ssalc-tsrif wef eht rof tsafkaerb edam ydaerla d’eh
dehs a otni notsuE nrut yeht tsriF"
naws deciov ylnrets a yb detpurretni saw eh ,derednaem eh sA
.yaw eht lla slaem erom gnikam
,srallip dna srodirroc etercnoc gnihctam yb rehtegot dnuob
,moor eht dnuora detrad seye s'kle ehT
.traeh sti deretne ti sa niart eht dnuora lla gnidnapxe mahgnimriB fo ytic eht
,revo kcehc lanif a flesmih evag mussop ehT
,deksa mussop ehT "?ew era erehW"
.rood regnessap eht ot dnuora dna
,flesmih koohs mussop ehT "...slaem
.selcatceps gnikool-evisnepxe fo riap a hguorht mih ta gnikool kle llat rehtar a ees ot
.notpmahtroN dna nodnoL ot dael hcihw
.deilper acsecnarF ".won
.mih fo deksat eb thgim tahw wenk sakuL os
...taht ta kool ,em kcuF"
.ssefnoc tsum I ,mroftalp eht no reppihc erom tol a demees uoy ,hguohT
,sehcaoc ssalc tsrif eht otni reh gnidael
,nehctik eht fo tuo kcab daeh sih dekop sakuL
,nwod tis ot dewolla saw eh rehtehw htiw deliot sakuL
.gninefaed saw ecnelis gnitluser ehT
,gniredduhs traeH ”.mehA"
.gnihtyreve revo wodahs sti tsac emarf leets eht dna mroftalp eht otni dils niart ehT
.srood fo tes rehtona ot hcaoc txen eht nwod dna yawgnag eht hguorht nur
seye sih ot hcihw
.won krow ruoy htiw tol a gnilevart eb ll'uoy esoppus I" .dehgual ttoillE
.tuo meht rehtoms ot swap sih gnisu
,mih ta pu derats sakuL
.rac teffub eht ni ecalp nekat sah erif llams A"
.tsal ta derettum eh
,retnuoc teffub eht revo dna nehctik eht ot yawrood eht ssorca gnihcaer saw wap A
.krowtniap der dlim dna yerg etisiuqxe dna
.niaga ecno ediug eht tuo dellup eh ,ylkciuq krow sih ssessa oT
,tekcop sih ni kcab ediug eht tup dna delbmurg eH
,aremac sih detfil sakuL ,detnahcnE
ertnec noitats suonrevac krad eht morf detrad seye siH
”?mmh ,no gge rehtona gnils ot hguone mraw s’evots eht fi rednoW
.tohsrae tfel dah ehs retfa sdnoces wef a deilper gnivah
,gnitatirri erom elttil a emaceb ti gnol erofeb tub
...taht tub fehc eht sa derih saw I"
,hhhu hO" .ti no nettirw ”acsecnarF“ eman eht htiw egdab llams a dah osla trihs ehT
,lufraF lacsaP yb
".eybdoog saw siht taht dekcolc t'ndah I
,daehrevo yks eznorb a htiW
,liaR hsitirB sgniht lla ekiL
.stixe eht sdrawot mroftalp eht nwod rehtruf gnivom
.ksed eht ot kcab denrut dna deggurhs neht
,egacdrib a fo erom won ,krownori tsav eht tuB
,yawrood eht morf gnihpargotohp trats ot ydaer ,aremac sih tuo koot eH
,tniap gnippihc htiw doots llits
saw sihT     .reggib hcum
.rehsiugnitxe erif a gnibbarg
noitom ni saw niart eht elihw no tfel eb ot erew sllirg eht taht
,setunim 51 ni emit dnoces eht roF
.ereht teg uoy ecno od dna ees ot erew ereht sgniht tahw dna
.sraey elpuoc a rof retnuoc siht gninnur kcuts neeb ev’I“ .delbmurg ehS
.ni efil sih hcum tneps dah eh sgnag rekib eht fo srehtael nrow ,derettab ,yttat eht toN
,enog gnol saw egdirb eht rof esoprup ehT
.tnew yeht sa pu tliub erom dna erom werg hcihw
,nnamrebod eht morf hgis rehtona gninrae
,emehcs ruoloc etihw dna kcalb sti ni gnimaelg
dna rood eht ot yaw sih edam sakuL ,niaga ecnO
.mih htiw ediug eht thguorb dah sakuL
deyortsed ro tsol ,degamad saw tahw gnikcots
,rehtona eno ot lleweraf devaw owt ehT
,tnemyolpme sih fo erawA
.droffilC yb niaga denepo saw rood nehctik eht ,tniop siht tA .dekrims eH ".elsilraC
.demriffa mussop ehT ".eno
,desuap nnamrebod ehT
.sselhtaerb ,roolf eht ot kcab gnillaf
”emitefiL a fo ediR“
,enola sakuL ot
.rorrim eht ni flesmih ta dekool dna
”,ti tuoba s’taht dna…“
.daeh sih gnisiar mussop eht
,nehctik eht fo edisni kcab deraeppasid sakuL ,ylhsipeehS
,sgniht ta gnikool og t'nod I fI !haeY"
.mih pots ot mra na tuo tup kle eht tub
,ll'I ,siht tuoba sraeh reganam ym fi ,doG"
.kcab deralg ylpmis droffilC
.ni deifilauq erew ttoillE ron sakuL rehtien dleif a
.delbmurg mussop ehT
,kle eht dniheb desolc rood ehT ".tsetal
,deffocs xof ehT .derettum eH ".si
,gnivom fo rennam rieht ni lauqe erew hcihw fo enon
retnuoc rab eht tsap
.nehctik eht pu tes ot nageb sakuL
.ti nrael ot evah d’eh demees tI
,yug gib ylriaf a saw eh ,rehtael nI
,nehctik eht ot kcab og ot denrut dna pu kcab wodniw eht dellup eh
”.em saw taht ,haeY“
,gniniart hsad-pals dna detimil sih htiw ecnadrocca nI
,nehctik eht ni dedeen t'nsaw eh erus ekam ot kcab ecnalg a koot eH ".sessap
,txet eht no sucof ot deirt seye siH
.tsez emos htiw gnihtemos gnikam ot derapmoc noitaredisnoc a yldrah saw mrof citehtsea tcefrep erehw
latipac eht fo eroc eht fo tuo yaw sti deldnurt niart eht
kcen eht rof gniws ot mih dlot gnideerb teerts sih
"?mahgnimriB dna senyeK notliM ,droftaW fo..."
.saw melborp eht tahw tuo dnif ot segairrac gnidnuorrus eht morf dehsur dah elpoep won yB
..." .delims mussop ehT ".sthgis
,esol ot boj on dna yllort a morf gnilles ni gniniart on htiW
.gnirettel ynihs ni ti nopu denozalbme "YTICRETNI"