tsgnoma tis I dna ,denrut sah noom ehT  .tnereffid era enob fo seno ehT
,tuh sih edistuo dnuorg eht nopu deyalps
stpmetta ruo esaec ew stseggus lálA nehw deveiler ma I .pleh ton seod
,tseuqer s’lálA ot secseiuqca yltnelis ehs tub ,ruf reh ni skaerts krad mrof sraet ;od ew retfa yltrohs sevirra heleB
.em hguorht dna revo swolf ti yletaidemmi dna
.swap depsalc no gnitser elzzum eninac rednels sih fo nihc eht
.mraw em speek tnemeticxe renni ym tub ,dloc eht ni sffup tniaf sekam htaerb ym—
.sedaf elgnit eht dna noitartnecnoc ym skaerb sseccus ym ta leef I edirp fo hsulf mraw ehT .etal oot s’tI
”…detcartsid teg t’nod
.gnihtemos gnitcepxe
.em rof ylkciuq sevloser ak-ner-tehK
.ezeerb eht fo pihw eht evoba sdnuos ylno eht era
,fles ruoy si aK .ak woN“
.nettalf srae yM ”!em rof gnitiaw erew uoy wonk ton did I ,yrros ma I“
hcihw ,won em serongi eH
,oga syad esoht lla tilps yeht nehw morf erom ecno gnitcennoc ,egrevnoc sevlah s’fles yM
.noos ereh eb lliw lálA tub—lairetam laitnesse eht htiw gnimochtrof naht erom neeb sah ruqeT—evrac ot deen I erom raf si erehT
.aam-tuhs-ab pu gnittes
.neddih mees sthguoht reh tub ,stneduts s’lálA fo lla fo tpeda tsom eht ylraelc si ehS
,hA .ylkciuq taht ti od rewef neve dna ,raf taht teg ynam toN“ .elzzum sih ssorca skaerb elims a dna ,pu thgiarts dnats srae sih fo stniop ehT ”!dooG“ .os
egassap fo etir ym ecnis reve gnitset s’lálA gnidaerd neeb dah I
.yaw taht daeh dna ,sevac ybraen emos fo wonk I .selit eht tcelloc dna ,nrettap s’etir eht peek I
hcihw ,ytliug erom leef em ekam ot sevres ylno tI .setir eht ecarbme ot diarfa ma I
.tuhs-ab tsac syawla ehs dias rubeK
.em denaol eh owt eht htiw gnola ,devrac ev’I xis eht tsuj si tI
.deirrownu smees lálA dna ,llewnu gnileef si eh emussa lla eW
ak nedoow a htob
.nwod kcab kool dna ,toh worg srae ym leef I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.akaR redaeltnuh ot klat dna ,egalliv eht ot kcab teG
.erutaerC-flaH tenretnI ruoy ,anueL yb daeR
.gniyrrac neeb ev’I raeps eht rof gab sih morf ak dna tehk em sedart lálA dna ,sdnalwol eht fo stserof ybraen eht ni evirra noos eW
.etaf s’rubeK otni ,si ti hguoht feirb ,espmilg a snepo shpylg enob eht fo rewop eht dna ,em ot ylisae semoc tI
.etir nevig yna fo seiradnuob eht nihtiw dedlom eb nac snoitcaretni rieht dna ,ynam era ereht
.em eciton ot dengied eh nehw ’buc‘ em dellac syawla eh rebmemer I dna ,ega ni em ot tsesolc si leyaH
.toh era srae ym dna ,em ta gnirats era srehto ehT
,ak htiw efas leef I erofeb elihw a eb lliw tI
.swen eht htiw derehtag egalliv eht emit eht yb eryp eht rof pu depparw neeb ylluficrem sah mrof sih—dlot erew ew tahw morf ,daeh eht ot wolb eguh a dereffus dah eH
,ecnalg raelc a eganam I nehw neve ,shpylg eht—
?ereh ehs si …sedis lla no ni gnisserp enots leef I tub ,krad si tI ?evac A !erehT
ytiuqitna fo ,sksam sti rednu hcihw ,raef redlo na :noitaredisnoc ruoy rof dettimbuS .dniheb  sevael ti ecaps eht llif lliw raef tuo nrub ot snigeb rats tsal eht nehw dna ,thgil sti fo segde eht dnuora knils ot ereht saw raef ,til saw
.su neewteb stis ,edih tfos fo edam ,senur fo gab ehT
,lla meht fo wonk I
.rehtona ni dleh ,dereves ,wap siH .erom gnihton
,gnigaruocne semitemos ,prahs semitemos ,lálA evitnetta eht fo stnemmoc lanoisacco eht dna selit fo kcalc eht dna
netsil ylerem ot ma I
”.tnaw uoy yaw revehcihw ,mrof ruoy gnola ssenerawa ruoy evom ot sucof a sa ti esu tsuj—
.syad wef txen eht revo egalliv eht ni ssensuovren elbaton a si erehT
,sevlesmeht seldnac eht hcaer I litnu llaw eht fo evruc eht wollof I .nac I sa ylihtlaets sa nihtiw ylwols yaw ym ekam I dna—?seldnac—
,tuo selit sekat eh nehw detaefed tsomla smees eH
,ti htiw sucof ym evom I ,enil eht swollof walc ym sa dna ,elit nedoow eht gnicart m’I hcihw htiw wap eht ta trats I .yrt I
.won su fo ruof eht tub si ti—
.seman eht naht erom on em dlot sah eH
.rehtegot meht teS“
.siht enod sah su tsgnoma enoemoS
.lálA ot ezag ym tfil I .sneppah gnihtoN
,espmilg a tsuj dnA .espmilg a hctac I emit eht yb ylivaeh gnitnap m’I tub ,rof tis I gnol woh wonk t’nod I
,suoregnad era enob fo setiR“
.oot ,shpylg wen fo em sllet eH
.sehsalF .sespmilG
.neewteb sllih eht yb derucsbo era ti fo sthgis dna dnuos eht
esu tsum uoy si snaem taht tahw ,arabaS
.leyaH rof kool I dna ,neht ,ak-ner-tehK
.selit gnilaets fo tneconni nevorp si ,oot ,eh tub—mih emalb t’nac I—pu swohs eh nehw devrennu yletelpmoc
.ydob sih sevael tirips sih sa ,txen semoc tahw ot eye s’dnim ym esolc I
.deworrob ev’I selit eht naht regnorts sleef shpylg eht gnitaerc fo tca eht nevE .selit ym evrac I dna
”.deen uoy eert eht ot uoy dael lliw ti spahrep ,ak-tehk mrofreP .og uoy ffO“
.niaga seirt eh tub
;edalb a htiw edam neeb evah ot demees gnireves eht
”.nelots neeb ev’yeht raef I .hcuop ym morf gnissim era selit enob emoS“
.elpmis ylgnisirprus eb ot tuo snrut tI
tnaem hcihW .pets tsrif eht dessap dah I tub—retsgnuoy yreve htiw did eh gnihtemos saw ti—
.gnorw si gnihtemos ;desserts si enot siH
,setir ruo gnitsac ,ereht tis ew sa
”?esoht fo eno morf evrac I t’nac yhW
.neppah nac tahw swonk ohw dna
,senur tsuj ton ,scigam tnereffid era ereht taht em sllet eH
.srae ym fo spit eht ot
.enob fo selit deniatsdoolb eht ot txen seenk ym ot pord I dna ,em liaf sgel yM .ti tpecca tonnac dnim yM
,ereh eurt si emas ehT
.kcab srae ym ,daeh ym ekahs I tub
.seitilibissop tsrow eht setaerc dnim ym sa
.tsewen ruo si arabaS“
,prahs si eciov s’lálA ”!hcum ooT“
…htrae eht dna sdniw eht ,latnem dna lacisyhp htob shtgnerts ,noitpecrep hcuot taht icoF
.moc.egallivukapam ta
si yrots s’thginoT dna
,enob fo elit eht htiw yad rehto eht pahsim ym ot eud kniht I ;gnisucof ytluciffid evah I .yrt eW
yletaidemmi tsomla ak-tehk htiw esimorp dewohs eH .elihwhtrow saw tiaw eht smees ti tub ,elihw a neeb sah tI
epahs eht fo knihT .ydob ruoy fo senil eht ecart ti leef ,enur eht fo senil eht ecart uoy sA“
.uoy uoy sekam taht gniht eht ,ecneserp ruoy
.reh rof hcraes lliw I .oG“
.nettogrof ma I neht tuB
.yllaudarg noitisnart dna elit nedoow a esu
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
gninrom-dim si tI
.shpylg eht tuo ekam tonnac I tub
.evirra ton seod ruqeT .tiaw eW
,yawa nrot neeb sah ti ekil sleef taht gnihtemos rof ylniav hctulc I
,tnedicca na ton saw siht
.tonnac doow daed fo eceip a taht yaw a ni sruoy enur taht sekam tI
.ak ruoy htiw flesruoy mlac ;deticxe era uoY“
.evirra ot tsal eht era ew raelc noos si ti dna ,egalliv eht fo tsew uaetalp eht no sdnalhtaeh eht ot daeh eW
.ereht derettaps doolb eht ta skcil eugnot a ,yllacidohtem
.ruqeT ta ecnalg a laets I dna ,rettoh worg srae yM
.enog si eh wonk I hguoht ,leyaH gnihtemos gnikees ,rehtruf flesym nepo I
”.nigeb ll’ew dna ,tser eht teem ll’uoY
.trats doog a s’tI“
.ti serongi eh tub ,ruf hsidder sih selffur dniw ehT
.luferac eb su sdib eH
dah su fo ynam—
,yllufknaht ,ylisae semoc noitatideM .em fo tnorf ni ak dna tehk ecalp I tub ,citsilpmis si tI
.yad eht fo snoitom eht hguorht gniog ,retfa noos tuh ym ta kcab flesym dnif I dna ,esrepsid ylteiuq eW
,eno thgir eht esoohc I
.nwerts selit dna em ediseb hcuop enur htiw
ot tey evah I senur fo seman eht
.em secudortni eh sa toh era srae ym dna ,elzzum ym pid I
.meht gnirettacs ,selit ym sekirts wap sih dna
.yaw eht fo tuo snoitatiseh ym sehsup taht ,gnidnatsrednu rof deen eht ,sucof eht si ti spahreP
.yrrow ot toN“ .selkcuhc lálA
desu saw ,elpmaxe rof ,ak-tehK
.gninrom ylrae fo llihc eht otni tuh ym fo trofmoc eht morf traped neht
,edih kid-kid tfos fo noitces a em htiw yrrac I
.niaga snigeb dniw eht ylneddus sa tsuj dna ,derrucco s’tahw raelc ekam eralg s’lálA dna ,nirg suoveihcsim s’rubeK ,elggig s’heleB .desirprus ,pu kool I dna ,ylneddus spots rehtaeh eht hguorht gniwolb dniw tnatsnoc eht ,tniop eno tA
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
.deneppah s’tahw su llet nac taht gnihtemos dnif ot gnipoh
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ti fo retteb kniht neht ,pu yaw ym ekam ot trats I
niaga yawa ,fles ym ,ak ym fo flah taht sehsup taht
.enob fo detfarc lareves era selit nedoow railimaf eht lla tsgnoma dna ,senur fo gab sih sdnepu lálA
.sniatnuom wol eht pota ,ereh pu sucof ot ysae si tI
.daer tonnac I ,hguoht ,ruqeT
,thgil nwad-erp eht ni dnuof si eH .si rubeK .hguoht ,txen ton ma I
.doolb eht ta skcil
.stneduts gnoma rehcaet a sa flesmih seirrac dna ,lla su naht redlo si ,esruoc fo ,lálA
eugnot a dna ,wap lakcaj der A
.gninrom txen eht pu wohs t’nseod leyaH
.emoh bmilc llihpu eht gnidaerd ydaerla m’I hguohtla ,gnol oot ekat t’nseod sdnalwol eht ot kert ehT
.noitaraperp ni selit enob ym tuo yal dna
—ti sa shtap eht gniwollof ,ti htiw rehtruf hcterts I dna ,sdaerps dna sdnapxe fles ym fo ssenerawa yM
.ecalp sti sekat raeps deneprahs a
.oga snosaes ynam saw taht tub—
.noitatidem ruoy ni ak enob eht dna
.dnuora esle eno on si ereht ;esnet I
;erofeb drazahpah demees dah yeht nehw won suoivbo mees selit eht no senil ehT
,snialpxe lálA ,ereh nwoD
”.senur tsrif ruoy tfarc lliw I dna uoy worromoT“
.gniteerg ni wap a sesiar
.rehtaeh dna enots eht tsgnoma stod hsidder ,elbisiv ylerab
,gnihtaerb ruoy wolS
hpylg ak a htiw elit enob a em sdnah ,esuap a retfa
.setamega era llacer I eerht dna ,em no snosaes lareves evah yeht—llew ton hguoht
.dnuof d’I tahw fo mih mrofni I ,sdrawretfa ,ylteiuQ
.drawrof peerc I oS
,demrofrep era slautir lleweraf eht retfa rehtag ylsuoicsnocbus ,dedulcni flesym
.hcterts stnemom eht sa mih nopu reivaeh dna reivaeh shgiew ti llet nac I dna ,tnelis si lálA
.su gnitegrat si enoemos taht raelc s’ti nehw ton ,dnah ym yats ot enob fo raef ym wolla tonnac I
.deliaf evah srehto erehw gnihtemos derevocsid gnivah ,leef I edirp eht pleh tonnac I dna desirprus si eH
,luferac eb ,uoy fo tser ehT
,etir sih strats lálA sa gnihctaw ,ylfeirb regnil I
”.erehT .gnihcuot era sedis eht os ,rehto hcae ot txeN
,was I tahw fo mih llet ot enola lálA gnihctac fo sepoh eht ni ,ylrae devirra I
.flesym sdniw eht dnammoc ot tiaw tonnac I
.em fo tnorf ni elit nedoow eht no devrac senil eht morf yawa em llup ot hguone ton si ti tub
.semalf eht morf gnittips skraps eht stcelloc yks thgin ehT
nrecsid nac I elttil si ereht tub ,hcuop enur nwo ym no krow I sa emit ot emit morf revo keep ot yrt I .ees
tnemeticxe s’enoyreve esnes nac I  .ak
,delliks era yeht nehW
,won rof detarapes elit enob eht evael I .ak-ak-tehK .nwo ym tuo yal I
taht snoitnem ylteiuq lálA dna
.wonk t’ndid ew selit hcihw esilaer dluow lálA htiw gniyduts su fo esoht tub eno oN
.resolc egrof I sa noitamrifnoc em sdeef ti dna
.niaga trats dna htaerb peed a ekat I tuB
.wap thgir sih gnissim ,yllug a ni ydob sih dnuof sretnuh gninruter ehT
,dnim ruoy ni tehk dloh uoy elihw ,ti ecarT
.ylnmelos ,setats eh
.scisab eht fo em ot skaeps eh dna ,ylwols kcab klaw eW ”.emoC
.sregnevacs rof laem elpmis a wap eht fo ssol eht ron
…lla ti fo erawa ,em fo trap hcae leef ot yrt I ,edisni kool I
.nwo ym fo setir gnimrofrep ot resolc pets eno gnileef ,drow hcae ecarbme I tub ,esruoc fo ,wenk ydaerla srehto eht sgnihT
.snaem taht tahw wonk I
ecaf a evah ot evorp yam
segde prahs htiw sedalb era yehT .snoitcetorp hcus on ,sdraug hcus on evah selit enob ehT .enob htiw
.dnuof si ydob sih nehw
.lla retfa ,em rof gnihton gniod si edisni gnittiS
,luferac ton era uoy fi—
.enob esu ees I tsrif eht osla si ehS ”.desucof yrev
cigam eht ot hcum oot flesym nepo I taht sgninraw sih yb denepmad netfo si sseccus ta erusaelp yM
.nrettap sti dloh dna ti tsac hcae ew ,evael ew sA
evac eht fo shtped krad eht morf rekcilf sthgiL
”,wohs t’nseod enoemos fi ees dnA
,heleB dna rubeK ,sniwt ehT
ralucitrap yna tneserper t’nseod flesti enil ehT“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ak-ner-tehk tuo yal I os
ylgnisirprus si tI .syas eh sa od I tub
,doolb ni derevoc llits era yehT
”.tey thguat t’nevah I seno ehT“ .sesuap eH
,selit nedoow llams owt dna ,won desolc si tI
.em nihtiw yaw sti sdaerht ti dna ,ti ot flesym nepo I
.draugefas a sa stca
,elit rehto eht ecart ot nigeb I sa selgnit llits
od llits nac tI .raeps detnulb a
,dednepu era sehcuop enuR
.taht ekil ton ,oN
.ksa I ”?seno hcihW“
.si taht ,seno nedoow ehT .nwo ym tfarc I litnu meht esu ot dettimrep eb lliw I dna ,erom dna senur fo gab sih ni eseht lla sah lálA
,til eldnac elgnis a ,tuh ym fo roolf eht no detaes flesym dnif I
.meht no sucof ,woN“
,noitatidem fo etir a rof
,wap ym morf doolb eht fo emos kcil I ,yllacidohtem
.gab sih ni kcab meht secalp dna selit owt eht pu skcip eH
nus eht htiw ffo nrub ot tey sah llihc eht dna ,ylrae si tI
”.esoprup siht rof emag emos tnuh ot nwod daeh lla lliw ew ,spahrep ,nosaes txeN
si ti—evil slakcaj der ew erehw sdnalhtaeh eht ni pu worg seert oN
dna tehk nedoow lamron eht htiw gnola
,won srehto eht
,deggelssorc ,tis I
.sdrawpu ylsselthgis gnirats
,nees s’eh sniur tsedlo eht fo emos tsgnoma dnuof eb nac ,syas eh ,selit eht nopu shpylg ehT
,sebirt tnatsid fo sdnal eht ni neve emos
.egalliv eht ot sdael taht htaptoof worran eht sdrawot epols eltneg eht nwod yaw ym ekam I
”.deeccus lliw su fo eno spahreP .hsiw uoy sa selit eht tsac os ,setir suoivbo on era ereht
,gab sih ni kcab ti secalp dna ak sekat eH
.enod tsomla si hcuop ym tub ,dessimsid era ew nehw
,mrifnoc ot kcehc I
.htaeh eht ot pu og dluohs ew esoppus I“
,dehsilbup yltnecer neeb sah taht levon a htiw gnola ,seirots trohs lareves nettirw sah ohw ,unutU yb
”?hcuop enur ruoy ees I yaM .arabaS“
.srehto eht morf trapa ,detcerid erehw tis I dna stniop lálA
.straped noisnet eht dna ,neht shgis eH
.yllufesoprup ,em sdrawot gnidirts lálA ees tub ,htaeh eht sdrawot pu trats I
.seunitnoc eh rof ,deciton evah tsum eH .yraw em sekam ti dna ,t’ndah I
,erofeb dekrow s’tI
…ab ro ak neve ,ner ,has ,tehK .stnih reffo nac taht sgniht ees yam ew ro
,srehto eht nioj ot ak hsup I sa
.sdon lálA dna ,raeh t’nod I gnihtemos srettum ruqeT .ti ni t’nera straeh ruo tub ,lamron sa su hcaet ot stpmetta lálA ,htaeh eht potA
.sredluob dna ssarg tub thguon htiw denroda ylralimis lla ,skaep gnitaludnu dna dehtooms erom tub dnuora esle gnihton si erehT
,dna stneduts rehto eht ot tuo meht fo lareves sdnah eH .esingocer I  seno lla era meht no shpylg eht neve—srehto eht ot ralimis yrev kool yehT
.dniheb owt ro edirts a ,lálA wollof I
.ti noitnem I nehw yad eno snirg rubeK
.senur ym evrac ti morf dna ,em ot skaeps taht eert a tceles nac I
.sebirt tnereffid fo syaw eht era yeht tub
”.erom rof yad rehtona nruter nac eW
.flesruoy tuc lliw uoy
.edalb a leper nac tI“
.railimaf os si tI
.oot ruqeT llems I
.senur esu ,stresed dna sannavas eht ni ,snisuoc lakcaj ruo neve toN .meht morf setir tsac ,’slakcaj der‘ eht ,rebekyK eht ,ew ylno tey
.enod sah fles rehto ym tahw ta
.ylluferac meht gnieye ,ssarg eht otno stnetnoc eht sllips dna sehcnuah sih no sehcuorc eH ”?ti si tahW“
,stneduts sih dna lálA
.ereht hcum os si erehT
,elohw eht sa rehtegot tcennoc senil esoht lla fi sa
”.rehto eht ot eno morf evom yllaudarG
,ytirailimafnu dna
.detcepxe evah dluow I naht regnol raf detiaw sah lálA taht noitasilaer eht htiw sedaf wonk I selit eht lla edam gnivah ton ta tnemtnioppasid ym dna ,yks eht ni wol si nus eht neht eciton I
,meht fo tnorf ni selit eht no desucof ,niarts qiqaR dna leyaH .ssarg eht no reh fo tnorf ni tuo daerps aam-aam-na-tehk ,weiv fo tuo dna ni srekcilf heleB
,selit fo gnirettacs A
,hcus sa dna ,htgnerts sti ot timil a sah tI .dednuob si
ak dna ner fo reffo s’lálA tpecca dna em dniheb ssensuovren ym tup I
.eurt si emas ehT“
.yltneitapmi tiaw srehto eht elihw ,kaeps ot snigeb lálA
.ytiralc otni kcab spans em dnuora dlrow eht dna ,os od I
,gnihctaw ,ybraen sehcnuah sih no sehcuorc lálA
.tcepxe I sa yltcaxe skool evac eht dna ,elcric a ni nrut ylwols I
.hcuop ym tuo ytpme dna ssarg eht ni tis I ,gnisuaP
”.lortnoc ni eb syawla tsum uoY
.snialpxe eh ”,mrof lacisyhp ruoy ,ydob eht si tehK“
,ees I tahw ni evila llits si eH
.esu sti nrael ot meht rof sbuc ruo ot ti evig nac ew tub ,egamad
?rehto hcae gnitcepsus er’ew tniop eht ot nettog ti sah—ti rof dab leef I tuB
”,ereh taht deen ll’uoy tbuod I“
,hcnerw a si erehT
…ekil si tI .emit emas eht ta meht morf detcetorp eb dna shpylg eht nrael ot su swolla tI
.gnidnatsrednu ni sdon lálA dna
.ereht dnob lanoitidda taht syawla si ereht dna ,niwt reh saw rubeK .elbalosnocni si heleB .wonk ot tnaw I kniht t’nod I dna ,taht naht erom on dlot ma I
.niaga flesym ma I dna ,dnim ym fo sessecer eht ni edih ot
has sah ruqeT .setir rieht krow srehto eht sa hctaw I
.hcuop ym ni kcab selit eht secalp eH
.elbaplap si ycnednopsed eht dna ,sseccus yna dah sah eno on—
”?enob tuoba tahW“ .syas lálA
”!doog yreV“ .gnillol eugnot ,em ta gninnirg si lálA
.edutitpa ym ta esirprus desserpxe yltnatsnoc sah lálA tub ,esruoc fo ,srehto eht naht shpylg rewef denrael evah I .setir fo smrof eht gnicitcarp
.mih ot ti dnah yltnelis I
.are on ot sgnoleb rorroH .ega on sah raeF
.noitatidem fo etir eht tpmetta I  unutU yb ”enoB dna dooW fo setiR“   yojne esaelP  .lla su ot nwonk
.doom ym tceffa ot elttil od leyaH morf eviecer I seralg suoivne dna detartsurf owt ro eno ehT
.evrac yllautneve ot epoh I senur eht niatnoc ot hcuop a gnikam flesym ysub dna ,setir rieht gnicart ecitcarp srehto eht sa
.tsrif eht tsniaga desserp llits
.niaga ti od dluoc I
”.taebtraeh ruoy wols
.etir deliaf taht morf trapa dehcnerw
,retne I sa eson ym snrub doolb fo tnecs ehT .eno tcerroc eht esoohc ot ysae si tI
.ti fo ytefas eht ni tfird dnim ym tel I dna
,retal sthguoht esoht terger I
”,niatrec rof ,enim gnisu naht retteb eb ll’tI .erofeb naht shpylg eht ot denutta erom neve era uoy taht
.erutaerC-flaH tenretnI ruoy ,anueL yb uoy rof daer ,unutU yb ”enoB dna dooW fo setiR“ saw sihT    .tiaw dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.selit eht no senil eht wollof seye ym tel I
.skool gnidnecsednoc sih htiw laed ot evah t’nod I
.tnemssarrabme dna ssol ni dnuorg eht ta erats I ,kcab srae ,ylivaeh gnitnaP
”enoB dna dooW fo setiR“
.nigeb yam uoy ,ruqeT“ .sseltimil tsomla si meht htiw od nac uoy tahw tuB
.niatrecnu m’I ,gninrael wen siht fo psuc eht no neve tub ,os od ot ehca I
rorroh htiw gnola ,nruter flah rehto taht fo seiromem eht dnA
lavivrus fo tcnitsni na si ti esoppus I
.ylsuoiruc ,walc a htiw meht fo senil eht ecart dna pu meht kcip I .ak dna tehK .ssarg eht ni ti ot txen eil ,sngised egnarts tub elpmis htiw devrac yledurc dna lanogaxeh
.ereht thgir m’I fi sa ,mih nopu nwod gnikool noisiv ym
.hcuop reh ni selit eht gniyalpsid
ydob ruoy fo trap
”,ti deen lliw uoy fo enon epoh I
,ssensuovren fo tnecs a ,ria eht ni noisnet a s’erehT
,niaga kees dluohs I fi ,em htiw ekat ot ak dna
”.etartnecnoc uoy spleh taht fi ,oot walc A
”.nruter I litnu uoy tcetorp lliw sretnuh sih dna eH
era yeht gnisilaer ,esingocer ton od I sdrow lanoisacco hctac I
.meht stcerid ak ym ecno mlac dnim dna traeh ym dna ,ysae
.ti syarteb tnecs s’ruqeT neve—
walc yM ”.mrof lacisyhp ruoy fo trap yreve fo erawa ak ruoy ekaM
tsael ta taht desaelp m’I
.eert gnivil a morf ti ekat tsum uoY“
.ti tcerid tsum I
htaeh eht no pu teem su fo tser ehT
.em ot sllac evac eht tuB
.erom ecno ydob ym ni kcab ma I dna
erif tsrif eht nehW
.nwo ruoy evrac ot redro ni ,flesruoy tnuh uoy gnihtemos morf ti ekat tsum uoY
”.ruqeT ,uoy naht neve rekciuq—
.flesym htiw noitartsurf ym repmet ot od nac I lla si ti dna
.noitcennoc eht ees dna
.yaw taht ti sekil ehS“
sdnuos tserem eht rof gninetsil diova ot elbanu ,tuh ym ni ekawa yal I sa sevren ym pleh ot gnihton seod hcihw ,emitnaem eht ni snossel ruo slecnac lálA .esrow sgniht sekam tsuj gniwonk eht dna ,egalliv eht ni ylekil si siht detarteprep reveohw taht wonk emos erus m’I
.pih ym nopu gnidir hcuop enur eht nihtiw rehtona eno tsniaga gnikcalc yltfos selit eht ot gniog yltnatsnoc dnim ym
;noitcartsid on sreffo ti neve tub
.setir ruo no krow ew tub
.ylgnitrofmoc wap ym stap eh rof ,noitanretsnoc ym deciton evah tsum lálA dna ,gnorw dna egnarts sleef llits gnihtemoS
;dnuof ev’I tahw gnidrager tnelis peek em sdib eH
,su llet nac tirips sih spahreP .yrt nac ew setir era erehT .kool nac eW“
.railimaf os won ma I hcihw htiw noitatidem fo etats eht niatta ylkciuq dna
.em dnuora noitcetorp sti evaew dna tem-na-tehk-bi tes I .noos ereh eb lliw eh setats eh dna ,nees ev’I tahw fo mih llet I .demrof si taht nrettap eht hguorht mih ot kaeps dna ,lálA kees I .ner-Á .hcuop enur ym pu nepo dna nrettap eht esaeler I ,daetsnI
kcilc tfos a si erehT
liat ym fo spit eht ot swaptoof ym fo spit eht morf ,ydob ym fo senil eht wollof I sa ti fo murht eht leef I dna
.roolf dloc eht nopu eil ,der htiw deniats dna enob lla
pup a sa yllanoisacco ereh deyalp dah I
.em gnihctaw ,ereht llits lálA dnif ot pu kool I taht etelpmoc si ti litnu ton si tI
,sehctaw eh sa rae na fo hctiwt lanoisacco eht tsuj ,niaga teiuq si lálA .od I oS
?flesreh sedih ehs spahreP
…tsuj ,hguone yldneirf s’ehS .dnim ot mees t’nseod lálA“
.hcuop ym ni kcab meht tup evah tsum I—revewoh ,tuoba derettacs t’nera selit enur yM .seitilibissop rof gnihcraes ,setir gnitsac peelsa gnillaf rebmemer I
.sredle eht ot klat ll’eh em sllet eH
.redluob llams a nopu stis eh sa nwo sih ot txen ti stes dna ,stnemmoc eh
,raf t’nsi egalliv ehT
.lla ton si taht dna
,won reisae si tI
.secnahc on ekat ew tub ,sredavni yna leper ot dah ew ecnis snosaes ynam neeb sah tI
.hcaorppa ruo eciton yeht nehw gniteerg ni wap a sesiar lálA dna ,su gnitiawa elcricimes a ni tis ,lla slakcaj der ,eviF
,ylwols neht ,edalb a sdloh wap s’lakcaj A
qiqaR dna ,selims ysae em hsalf
.woh gniwonk ton tub pleh ot gnitnaw
,ekih eht eciton ylerab I tub ,nruter ew emit eht yb krad si tI
.delbuod era stuocs ruo ,gninrom eht htiW
”.meht wollof uoy sa sucof dna
.llew sa sesu rehto dah ti fles fo ecnesse eht dna ydob eht neewteb noitcennoc a sa tey
ner em sreffo eH
.egalliv eht ta pu doow fo sehcac
.em ta llup seert eht ydaerla dna ,raf levart ot evah t’nod I
.gninrom worromoT“
.cinap ot egalliv eht tnaw ton od ew
.si ti tahw ees ot deen I dna ,ereht gnihtemos si erehT
.ylkciuq mrof sekat hcuop eht—erofeb rehtael nwes ev’I .ksat ym ot dneb I oS .gnihton naem
.tsehc sih ni devrac eloh a si erehT
,llirht ym sserper ot tluciffid si tI
,ylevitatnet ,yebo I
.shgual eh ”,ti od dluow enoyreve ,elpmis taht erew ti fI“
.gnikniht ereht dehcuorc llits ,lálA ta kool I
,edivorp ot seunitnoc nrettap ehT
lálA llet I dna ,selgnit tI
.noitcerid ym ni sdon ehs esuap a retfa dna ,elims thgils dna worbeye desiar a noitome fo layarteb ylno reh ,em sehctaw ehS
.gninrom gniwollof eht nekawa I nehw detsuahxe ma I
.od ew tahw si hcihW .syas eh
era heleB dna qiqaR ,evael I emit eht yB
,nepo oot era uoY“
.sseccus eht htiw gnireviuq llits m’I tub ,og meht ees ot das tsomla m’I
.em stpurretni lálA emit eht yb nezod a flah detelpmoc ev’I
.sucof ym esaeler ot em llet lálA raeh ylmid I .erutan rieht dnatsrednu ot trats I leef I dna ,sgniht dnib dna enifed htob yeht
,ylwolS .mraw llits
,enob fo elit tnereffid a enola tel
,meht evrac uoy ecno ,dnif lliw uoY
”.teem ew nehw stsac ehs etir tsrif eht s’tI ?deciton uoy t’nevah—tuhs-ab dniheb sedih ehS
dnuof eb nac dna
.mra ym pu ylwols gnivom
,sllaf thgin retfa ,yllanif dna ,em ta sllup ssenkaew nwo ym ta noitartsurF
evah eW“ .hgih oot
smees qiqaR dnA .nwo reh ylnO
.ybraen gniyl ruqeT fo ydob nekorb eht gnitanimulli ylmid
,em tcerid ti tel tonnac I—
.ereht regnol on si ti tub
.edisniatnuom eht ni sevac lareves morf nwod sepols taht eercs eht tsdima gnidnats flesym dnif noos I
.yllufsseccus ti mrofrep nac ew litnu ti taeper ew taht tnetsisni—tem-na-tehk-bi—etir wen a su sehcaet eH .etal si eh tub
,mih sedave etir eht sa delleuq ylkciuq sllac eh sdniw eht ,selggurts rubeK .desolc seye reh htiw ylmlac stis dna ,tuo dial hka-
.dnim ruoy htiw meht fo senil eht ecarT
.sdrawpu daeh ym gnitlit dna elzzum ym gnippuc ,yltneg syas lálA ”,arabaS
.mih morf trapa ,su fo tpeda tsom eht saw ehS
;daerht tug emos dna ,lwa na
.em esirprus t’nseod
.krowidnah ym erolpxe ot revo tfihs I
.sniojer ak ym—ylfeirb os ho—ylfeirB .rebmemer I sA
.reh emalb su fo enon dna ,eveirg ot tuh reh ni ffo flesreh sesolc ehS
,lairetam a sa ,dooW .selit enur nedoow eht htiw won railimaf era uoy ,arabaS“