si yrots s’yadoT dna
"?sluos gnirehtag eb uoy t'ndluohS"
.ynnaryt sti morf deerf eb lliw roop ehT
.revol suolaej eht etiuq nairaM dnuof dah sretsnom fo stros llA
.diova ot gnihtemoS
.roliat-xof lufituaeb a yb dednem gnieb fo dnim s'niboR ni derrits snoitcelloceR
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.htgnel s'worra eht nwod dereep dna worra eht koot ehS ".si tI"
,gninnuc hcus htiw delims enoN
"?trats uoy od erehW .sey
,lennahc ebuTuoY sisylana larutluc
,uoy tuoba sgnos wen nips lliw sdlaks eht dna tsaeb siht lliK
".tsixe ylerab sseleman ehT
"?pu em reehc dluow siht wonk uoy d'woH"
.hgis a htiw dedaf htrim s'namuh ehT
.elims tniaf a htiw daeh reh koohs rehcra ehT
,seye s'xof a htiw tuo dekool ehs ,namuh hguohT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
".daeh s'nomed lanoisacco eht dnA
.diov eht otni ffo rehtaef dna droc fo sparcs eht dehsurb ehs
,eid yeht retfa sraey derdnuh A"
.elbissopmi gnilias evorp ton seod taob gnikael A"
".thgin eht morf edih dna srood rieht rab snamuh ehT
.worra eht ot repsihw a dehtaerb nairaM ".seman
.namow a m'I rebmemer neve t'nod yehT
.kcohs tuohtiw tub
,sgniw reh neewteb tes ot depahs ,dleihs A
.reh dniheb krab fo ffucs A
.reviuq reh morf tuo gnikcits gnihctelf eht gnola wap a dehsurb ehs ,gnidnatS ".seirutnec
,ynroht werg stirips dnaldoow ehT
gnidih sti morf ti hsulf lliw ew ,rehtegoT"
efink lufesu tsom sih fo kniht dluow ,daed sraey eseht lla
.seirutnec tfiws fo
sruof lla ot deppid eiryklav ehT
.kcab worra eht dednah ehs ,noitubirtnoc reh ta gniddoN
".revo nettirw dna tnemhcrap eht morf deparcs si esle gnihtyrevE
.elzzum rednels reh no enohs feihcsiM
.daehworra na dna gnihctelf dettif dna
.enot reh ni gnar ytinretE ".regnol I dnA"
.rehcaerB-norI ,afújR-nráJ
.noitcani rof esuac t'nsi tahT
,hguob eht dnuora depparw llits sgeL
.enipluv yleritne saw elims reh hguoht
,erac htiw detaert eb ot dah rolav fo tirips a yb desselb nopaew A
ni denael nairaM ".efiwesuoh
:esaelp ,efil naht erom evol I mohw
.ti gnippirts nageb dna
.elohw nettogrof era tsoM"
"?ecnedicnioc a t'nsaw noitasrevnoc elohw siht ekil leef I od yhW"
,ediw deppalf sgniw evissam reH
,thgieh siht morf gnillaf neve taht gniwonk
,sehcnarb ybraen otno gnihctulC
thgin eht sklats tI
"?neht nidO fo nevar A"
.roolf tserof eht ot sdray nezod a delbmut
".ylf meht tel yam uoy os
.thgilf ni tfird dluow ti woh tsuj reh dlot
.kool derit a eiryklav eht tsac ehS ".raed ym ,laedi elbon A"
.sraey rof gnidnet neeb d'ehs hcnarb eht dnuof ehS
.temleh reh fo sgniw leets eht tsniaga deleviws srae kcalb-tooS
”eiryklaV reH dna dooH niboR“ saw sihT
.sdne rieht sevres tahw ylno rebmemer yehT"
.dellik tog ohw ,dooH niboR"
,lisardggY eert-dlrow eht nwod dna pU
.hcnarb eht no deggel-ssorc tas dna sserd reh dehtooms nairaM ".ytic eht nI
.sworra reh eb yad eno dluow taht sgiwt gnidnet ,hguob a no tas dooH niboR   ~ ~ ~   opmeT yb
.won neve ,niamer uoy namuh woh tegrof I .evol ym ,evol yM"
".em niatsus t'nseod htaeD .nevar on m'I"
.evol htiw reh nopu dekool ron
,elprup-gnineve na morf tuo gnikop
.keehc reh tsniaga elzzum mils reh debbur dna
.slive fo retnuh ,dooH niboR
"?trats I od erehW"   ".aes
.elbarenluv dna roop eht yals ot sgnidliub spael dna
stoohs dna sevaeL
.egap ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna sserP tenalPruF yb
.sdnah reh ni worra eht htiw deyot niboR ,tsacnwod seyE
"?erutaerc siht si tahW"
"…gnilrad ym ,ksa dluohs uoy etanutrof woH"
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.nairaM naht reitraeh dna regnorts seiryklav dleh dlrow eht ,seY
.gals ot gnihtyna stlem taht ecanruf gniraor a htuom stI
.sgel dessorc erofeb detnalp swap tnorf reh
.ylerar emac serutnevda hcus ,sdnaldoow eht dewollaws ssergorp sa ,hguoht ,woN
".deman os era weF
.elzzum yhtoot taht morf deohce hgual eltneg s'namowelbon A ".elbissopmi
".nairaM diaM ylevol eht dna ,dooH niboR
".slocotorp enivid eht evresbo tsum eW
.sgnaf xof etihw elttil gnilaever
:tuo gnar eciov A
.dekciw enog gnik eht fo esruc eht ro
.eciov reh ni delbmur rednuht desumA
.receiP ro retiB ekil
.redluohs reh revo gnillaf liatynop ytsur
,ecnalab rof daerps sgniw
,gniteelf revewoh
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.keehc s'devoleb reh dehcuot dna
dehsub liat tahT
,toof eno no gnilriwT ".gnignol
.spil reh no wap erumed a decalp ehs
,efink reh gniwarD .eurt dna
,kcab kool a tsac ehS
.gnileef eht derovas ehS
".ma I ohw rednow semitemos I"
"?riapsed uoy od yhw nehT"
.niboR raed ,ssendnof morf yrettalF"
,decarb ylluferaC
eiryklaV reH dna
.retfa dna körangaR llit enim era uoy yhw ecneH
,wap s'eiryklav-xof eht ni dnah reh decalp ehS
~ ~ ~   .reh evas dluow sgniw s'revol reh
.yerp ruo ti ekam dna eloh-
,snolat ekil tes swap reh
".ydaerla ti terger I"
revol ruoy ma I esuaceB
.em tuohtiw dedrehpehs eb nac daed cioreh ehT"
".ecived gnitfil delgnafwen emos s'taht em llet
.seye reh desolc niboR ,naorg a htiW
.erac htiw ti koot rehcra ehT ".detsixe
,bmil eert eht pota reh ecnalab ot esae etulosba htiw detfihs liat reH
.htaed fo ytniatrec eht htiw delkcuhc nairaM ".elohw
.keehc s'namuh eht dessik ehS ".retfa
.efink gnitnuh s'remraf a neeb ecno dah tahw fo lemmop eht no wap reh detser ehS ".won
,nairaM ma I esuaceB"
,sevrawd eht yb derotser dna tsacer ylsuoluciteM
.sevorg dercas eht fo erom deruoved yrtsudni ,raey yrevE
.esruoc fO"
".srobal ruo hguorht wena nrob si llA
"?selddir kaeps t'nseod ohw gnieb rehguor ,relbon A"
".gninetraehsid s'tI"
.seye reh dellor niboR
.dehcneuq eb tonnac taht erif a era uoY"
.desrun yeht segdurg eht fo kaeps reven dluow tub
.gnos evol a ekil sdrow eht detlil dna
,dehgual nediam-xof ehT
,lrans detareggaxe na ni daerps spil reH
.taob retteb a dliub eW .taob eht xif eW"
”eiryklaV reH dna dooH niboR“
,thgit dettonk droc tsal eht htiW
.nwoner eurt fo era uoY"
.efiwesuoh lufitud a ekil ,rehtegot kcab uoy wes lliw I"   ".niagA"
seman elpmis meht detnarg ehs ,yllausU
.nus eht ni demaelg tlep egnaro s'legna-raw a ,hcnarb eht nwoD
"?niboR teews ,retteb gnileef ton uoy erA"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dlrow eht ot denruter neerg dna der neewteb ecnereffid ehT
.secnedicnioc dna smihw ni laed ton od dnik yM"
.doow fo htgnel elbaecivres etiuq
.tsehc yffulf reh ot sdnah s'namuh esoht dehctulc ehS
.eman reh erob taht syalp dna selat fo llac eht tsiser t'ndluoc ehs tub
".emit gnol a devil ev'I tuB"
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,nuK'O epmeT yb
.nwod sraew dlrow ehT"
.ecnatsid eht ni yrtsudni fo ekoms eht drawot kcab dekool ehS
,keehc reh no deregnil htmraw thgilS
.sdog eht ot yhport a sa esproc sti tneserp lliw eW
.dnim s'enoyna ni gnihcte ruoy neprahs ton lliw doow yldnik siht ni gniyatS
,hguob a no doots dooH niboR
,ecarg s'ssecnirp a htiw devom ydob reH .sserd sselmaes
.delims namuh ehT
".skcirt htiw tnuh I .flow on m'I"
.detsurt eb ot ton erofereht dna namuh a
".em srettalf ehs fi nevE
:ecafrus sti otni deredloms senuR
.evol fo tuo ylno ton
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sreh dehcuot eson kcalb dloc taht sa reh htiw seye dekcol niboR
,mmH"   ".egnahc t'ndluow dlrow eht dna noihsuc-nip a otni renwo yrotcaf taf yreve nrut dluoc I
.srennam doog era su morf tnaw yeht lla
.swalc tnulb rieht htiw neve
,ecitcarp fo seirutnec htiW
.sdrow deyenoh htiw reh ylp nexiv eht tel ot naht retteb wenk ehs tub
.eman ruoy ohce reverof sthguoht yM"
.reh ta worra eht fo hcton eht devaw ehS ".dellik
.eaf eht htiw dah eno snoitasrevnoc egnarts eht neve dessim ehS
"?sterces fo hctulc a dna xyno fo kaeb a dna thgin fo sgniW"
?efil yb detaert-lli uoy erA
.enilyks eht gnittolb ekoms yrotcaf eht nopu
.aes eht nodnaba ton od ew tuB
.krowidnah htiw emac
.doog ytterp si eno tsal taht esoppus I"
.semit dnasuoht a dah d'yeht noitasrevnoc eht ta elttil a delims niboR
tleb reh ta hcuop a otni deppid sdnah reh
.efiw s'eno saw tirips eht nehw yllaicepse
.tnelis welf eiryklav a fo sgniw ehT
sworra enif hctelf ylno uoy esuaceB"
,drows lartsecna na reh gnivig tnaem eiryklav a gniyrraM
yrevarb ruoy tuoba moolb lliw selat hserf
.kcab reh no enohs
.noitanimaxe rof tuo worra wen eht dekcilf ehS ".doog
a si kcaJ deleeH-gnirpS ehT"
.sregnif reh ni worra eht delriwt ehS
.oot dlrow eht fo trap era eW
.latem fo swalc dna romra fo hselF
.ria ytpme otni sgel reh dekcik rehcra ehT
llafdniW gnidulcni skoob fo rohtua dna
.eenk s'rehcra eht gnola wap thgindim a decart nairaM
".revol yM .stnaryt fo enaB
.ytilauq ni dnif ot reisae emoceb dah ,tsael ta ,leetS
,daeh reh koohs ehS
a delttihw dah ehs ,nooS
,dehcnilf rehcra ehT
,tseretni htiw drawrof denael neht
.delims ehs sa dehctiwt sreksihw reH
.revol reh ecaf ot denrut ehs
,ni denael eiryklav ehT
.rewoc ton od uoy tey dnA"
.krow reh derimda ehs
".nwod raet deerg fo serif eht ,dliub I revetahW"
".dlrow eht retteb uoy esuaceb os did I
desserppo tnasaep eht fo epoh eht ti eb
dooH niboR :yojne esaelP
.oreh namoeY .rehcrA .waltuO
"?daetsni revol a rof uoy nekat dah eiryklav-flow a hsiw uoy oD
.skaerb dlrow ehT
.deniur krow nwo ym nees ev'I"
.ngis doog a reven saw erutaerc larutanrepus a morf msaisuhtne hcuS
thgiarts nworg dah ti
,ecaf s'revol reh ees tsum I sa hcus erutaerc etaciled A
ecitcarp fo seirutneC
.hgual a deffins niboR
tsael eht tub ma I
.dniw eht ni decnad sreksihW
?niboR raed ,gnos das a hcus yhW"
".kcaJ deleeH-gnirpS eht ti llac yehT"
,tnemhsilpmocca fo esnes A
.loot mraf a saw drows taht fi neve
"?tuoba gniklat ew era tahW"
,gnihtyreve evah sdog eht ecniS" .delkcuhc ehS ".esruoc
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
"?uoy fo tfel s'taht lla s'eman a nehw ,eman a s'doog tahW"
,weiv rieht ni ,deniamer niboR
.htiw elfirt ot gnihton llits saw seiryklav fo tsael eht neve tuB
.won eman a tub gnihton m'I"
eerf ti decils ehs
.gnignol fo psiw a ot yawa etsaw I tsel
.sretsnom fo stros lla ot yerp gnitpmet devorp cigam htiw deubmi namuh A
.seman ni rewop eht swonk eiryklav A"
.sraey fo sdnasuoht ni raeppa ot nomed fo dnik wen tsrif ehT .nomed
.pih reh ta drabbacs depmats-yletacirtni na ni gnuh ti
.niaga namuh a fo esoht emoceb ot seye reh dewolla niboR   ".nairaM ,olleH"
".eiryklav eht fo tselbmuh dna
.niboR raed ,eof reihtrow hcum A"
.legna na fo noissessop derusaert tsom eht gnieb
,gnilrad ym ,nairaM"
.ezeerb eht tsniaga tah reh nwod dellup dna deggurhs niboR ".deniur
.ti evorpmi eW .ti riaper eW
.worra na rof eman ddo nA
".tsen reh rof skcits gnirehtag ,niboR ym sehcrep hcnarb a nO"
,erehwemos dniw eht no gnir ton eman ruoy seod reveN
".erew yeht ohw rebmemer enon
.sega rof tsal ot seno
.detsixe I wonk ot desserp-drah eb dluow elpoeP"
.yb decnad ezeerB .deprihc sdriB
.nirg gnimaelg a htiw reh ot delleporp dna
,ylniatrec ,tibah niav A ".renommoc a rO
dnah s'rehcra eht koot ehS ".niboR
,rehtaf reh tahw derednow niboR
htaed morf uoy elots I"
.sgniw reh evoba decnuob dna
.nediam-wob ,dooH niboR
.ecaf s'revol reh morf riah ytsur fo kcol esool a dehsurb nexiv ehT ".secnedicnioc
.ma I ohw rof em srebmemer enoemos tsael tA"
.sworra htiw stnasaep eht eerf t'nac I"
.nwonk eb nac deman ehT"
.nesira sah wen gnihtemoS"
.reviuq reh otni giwt a neeb yltnecer os dah taht worra eht gnippils
yrruf d'F yllarutluC eht ta retirw ffats eht si ohw ,nuK'O epmeT yb
.eiryklav eht fo tserevelc ,xoF ehT
.tsaeb eht tsniaga
.hguob eht dnuora gnisnet sgel
.stsaerb reh ssorca gnirtswob eht nwod regnif a nar rehcra ehT ".elttil A .heH"