,dnuora ydob sih denrut nilloC nehT
.nwod daeh sih dekcud yllautcnitsni ekalB dna ,pu denepo rood ehT
:drawrof tniop siht morf eurt saw gniht eno taht wenk eh
.dleif eht sdrawot tfel daeh sih gninrut ,enirevlow eht morf pu dekool ekalB
,sessalc rieht rof tfel yehT ".noos
.elbissop sa yllausac sa ti ot resolc dna resolc dehcni dna sroolf eht deppom eH
.reduol gnikaeps rehtaf s'nilloC raeh dluoc eh dna trohs tuc saw eH "—tsuj ,daD
.tey ekalB ot gnicnalg neve ton ,dias eh
”nuR“  fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.eit sih tsujda ot pu wap eno dehcaer eh ,did eh nehw dna
,niaga gnar mrala ehT
,gnihtemos detcepsus ev'thgim yeht fi nevE
elims yhtoot ediw taht tpek eh tub ,gnileef eht tog ev'tsum knuks ehT
,drah dnuorg eht tih ekalB
,niaga meht denepo eh nehw dna ,emit ni tsuj seye sih desolc kcirtapztiF .rD
—txen eht fo dne eht yb bal eht ni t'nsaw eh fI
.pihsrow yreve gnirud deyalp yeht dnab kcor naitsirhc emas eht t'nsaw taht cisum draeh d'eh emit tsrif eht saw siht
,noitnetta lluf sih dah xof eht erus gnikam ,ni denael ekalB
,deksa eh ,kcab flesmih dloh dluoc eh erofeB
.kcud srae s'yob rehto eht ekam ot hguone repap gniraet eht fo dnuos eht
"?huh ,sdohtem lanoitidart eroM"
,deeps ni egnahc eht rof detiaw ekalB
.yltnetni moorssalc eht fo retnec eht ni kcolc eht dehctaw ekalB
.gnitoof sih gnihctac erofeb dnoces a rof gnilbmuts ,yaw eht fo tuo tpael yksuh ehT
.dranreB morf pleh dna edis derujninu sih htiw pu flesmih  llup ot gniyrt
.mih ffo seye sih ekat ot detnaw eh fi erus ton
.guh thgit a otni mih gnipeek
,repsihw dna ksed sih revo denael kcirtapztiF .rD
,dekool eh suoivbo woh erus t'nsaw eH
.sgnileef esoht otno dloh ot drah ti edam eciov sih ni esromer eht tub
,kcuF" .hcnilf lufwa na edam eh ,mra sih evom ot derit eh nehw dna
.eltsihw dehctip hgih eht ta srae rieht dedlof
toof thgir sih otni thgiew tup eh ,htgnerts sih fo lla htiW
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.deirc dna dehgual htob eh
.rebmem ytlucaf a syawla
.dehserfer tub ,sselmaerd ,txen eht pu ekow eh neht dna dnoces eno peelsa saw eH
.lamron t'nsi sihT"
.taht retfa gnihtyna yas t'ndid eH ".enif
,gniralb llits saw mrala erif ehT
.enog erew epacse fo secnahc sih
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta dna
,derepsihw dna guh thgit a otni esuom eht dellup eh ,dranreB htiw moor eht tfel eh erofeB
”nuR“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.derevoc ylluf saw eh litnu flesmih revo stnap dna ,stekcaj ,strihs gnillup nageb dna elip eht otni flesmih evod eh ,noitpo rehto oN
,thgiarts gninrut tuoba seil cilbup delddep yliraropmet evah ohw elpoep fo lufdnah a ylno mialc nac srednefed stI
,seye deniap htiw pu gnikool
,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
;seton gnitirw neve t'nsaw eh ,tniop emos tA
.ereh degnoleb eno oN
.erom ecno denepo imes eht ot rood eht erofeb ruoh-flah rehtona tiaw ot dah ylno ekalB
,dehgis dna daeh sih koohs eH
.stsermra citsalp eht gnihctarcs morf spit rieht peek ot smlap sih nepo ot dah eh dna dexelf swalc siH
.airetefac niam eht morf weiv fo tuo neddih saw taht
.llits doots dna desuap eh ,moor gnitiaw eht otni tuo tog eh sA
.etarbelec dluoc eerht eht dna
,imes a fo kcab eht ni bac ynit eht ot denifnoC
dna gnimocni ylno
,delbmurg dna ,ti ees t'ndluoc knuks eht fi neve desopxe sgnaf ,detsiwt elzzum s'ekalB  ".ay
,ezag sih htiw mih dewollof ekalB
yawllah a saw nehctik eht dniheB
,kaeps ot htuom sih ro evom ot sgel sih teg t'ndluoc ekalB
,ytinutroppo tcaxe siht rof gnitiaw neeb lla d'yeht ekil
.enod ti teg ot gniog saw eh woh wenk eh erus saw eh dna nalp sih ot pets tnatropmi erom eno dah ekalB
dnoces yna neppah ot gniog saw ti taht dedneterp eh dna
.elzzum sih ni etsat rettib a tfel stnerap sih fo thguoht ehT
.uoy fo duorp os m'I" ,gnidda
2 trap ,etoyoC triD yb
.eldnah latem eht nwod decrof dna ti otni demmals yllacitcarp netram enip ehT
denettalf saw enilef ehT
,tliug emos leef tub pleh t'ndluoc ekalB
.flesmih ot derepsihw eh ",hO"
,dexif deniamer elims sih hguoht dna
,ylthgit desolc saw elzzum siH
,mrod eht otni dna sllah eht hguorht yaw sih depmots dah eH
,sfeileb ruoy ot snoitcidartnoc yna dnif uoy fi taht diarfa er'uoY .diarfa er'uoY"
ni nworht neeb dah srepap eht noitcerid eht ni dekool ekalB ".uoy
.nwo ym no eseht revo og annog tsuj saw I"
.enilpicsid emos sdeen sruoy fo edutitta taht tuB"
,keew gniwollof eht kcirtapztiF .rD htiw gniteem sih rof tiaw ot dah eH
.gnihctiwt spil ,tuhs deriw saw elzzum siH .gnikahs ydob
.mih trofmoc ot deirt yeht sa tsetorp t'ndid eh dna ,esolc mih dleh yehT
,rehtegot moor eht ni tas syob eerht lla ,dnekeew eht gniruD .2 fo
.tuo derettum nilloC
esuba suoigiler ro ,lailimaf
”nuR“   yojne esaelP
.wam sih ni sgnaf sih gnidnirg
.tuo elim a neeb evah t'ndluoc eh dna setunim ni enod saw ti ,yllaeR
,yltalf gniyas erofeb dnoces a detiaw eh dna rehtegot ylthgil desserp deniamer spil siH
.bmun tnew sregnif ym litnu swap ym ni eci
.noitats bal eht dniheb gnivid yllacitcarp ,drawrof deirrucs dranreB dna
.gnihtemos yas ot ekalB detcepxe eh ekil ,emulov wol a ta deniamer cisum ehT
,edis eht otni dehsarc eh dna
.s'ekalB teem ot kcab gnikcilf seye sih ,elims a ni kcab llup elzzum s'leunammE was eH
.ffats gninaelc eht mrofni ot erus eb ll'I
.nilloC tuoba yrrow ot nageb eh ,hguoht dessap etunim rehtona nehW
.ksed sih otni gnimmals tsif
mih eciton neve t'ndid noil eht
,ekalB no denruter stils enipluv esoht
.xaler ot flesmih dewolla eb taht
.mih evael ot tnaw t'ndid eh dna
,imes eht fo enigne eht naht retsaf gnikrow saw niarb s'ekalB ".tihs
.taht ta elbatrofmocnu leef tub pleh t'ndluoc netram enip eht dna
.siht ees meht tel t'nac uoy ,tsrif
.ereht thgir nwod nworht evah dluow ekalB
.uoy tcerroc ot sdohtem lanoitidart erom gnisu deppots ew ykcul er'uoy dnA"
"?ereh elbaresim os ti sI"
.skeew tsap eseht devorpmi yllaer ev'uoY"
.enirevlow eht dehctaw dna thgit rehto hcae dleh yehT .s'dranreB no wap a
.ksed eht fo edis rehto eht no ylmrif saw ti erus edam xof eht tub ,kcab meht barg ot deirt netram enip ehT .gnineppah saw tahw dezilaer neve eh erofeb ekalB morf yawa ti depoocs eH
.supmac eht fo nwal tnorf eht sdrawot gnicar nageb syob eerht lla ,yletaidemmI "!nuR"
.noos mrala eht llik ot gniog erew yeht taht gniwonk ,dnim sih pu ekam ot dah ekalB
.tuo lla ti tel eh sa
,uoy brutsid ot ylekil si
,seye sih esolc ot detnaw ekalB
.ti rof llef yeht dna snoitcurtsni ekaf eht meht dewohs enirevlow eht taht depoh eH
.seY" "—deen t'nod I"
tekcaj mined a neewteb shtaerb llams ekat saw od dluoc eh llA
.sehtolc fo elip eht htaenrednu
.daehtihs a eb annog er'uoy fi tsew yaw eht lla uoy ekat ot evah t'nod I tub
.raf uoy teg annog t'nia tihs taht tub
.sruoh rof gnitsal
,taht ta dehcnilf ekalB
.rehtie tuo dnif ot dnuora kcits t'ndluoc eh tub
.ecnahc a dnats t'ndid esuom eht taht gniwonk ,hteet sih tirg eH
.moor eht ni rood rehtie ot hctal eht nwod depat dna
.mih rof sgniht dne ylerus dluow taht
.tuo daeh sih gnikop erofeb wodniw ssalg elttil eht hguorht keep kciuq a gnikat ,bal eht fo rood rehto eht ot devom eH
.eson sih nwod gnilbbird tons htiw pu gniraet
,yrros a tuo tel ot emit evah t'ndid eH
.dnim ot emac gniht eno ylnO
",ti fo erac ekat ll'I
.delb selkcunk sih litnu loohcs eht fo renroc yreve burcs ot dah eH
.mih ta ti devaw dna kcab mra na hcaer revewoh did rekcurt ehT
,retsaf evom ot meht egaruocne ot gniyrt ,dnuora daeh sih denrut ekalB
gnideen tub ,regna eht ekaf ot gnideen ton ,slirtson sih hguorht ni dehtaerb eH
ypareht noisrevnoc fo mrof eht ni
,mih fo tnorf ni sucof sih denruter ekalB
.drawrof flesmih degnul dna
.ti edisgnola pu dewohs reven nilloC ron dranreB
.delbmurc ev'thgim nirg mlac taht esle ro
.daor eht no desucof seye
.mih ta gnivaw xof eht ees ot denrut eH "?ereht ni uoY
na evah ot deen on s'erehT
.ti was eh nehw s'tahT
,yob a tsuj llits saw eH
.ereh ni saw eh tluaf sih yllaitrap saw ti ekil
.ekalB ,lamron ton er'uoY"
,detaeper eh ",em was stneduts wef a kniht I tub
.mih rof gnillac era stnerap siH
,taht fo thguoht eh nehw dnA
,elzzum sih tsniaga mra sih deggard eh ,daetsnI
eulc emos flesmih gnivig ,sniatnuom eht ta dekool eH
.did yeht tiaw dnA
.edis rehto eht morf dias kcirtapztiF .rD
,drawrof repap fo eceip llams eht devohs xof ehT ".erus eb ot tsuj
",roivaheB .edutitta
.tif doog a ekil mees t'ndid
.ti otni tog yllaer uoY
",uoy teg I kniht I
.mih ta eralg naht erom hcum od t'ndluoc ekalB
.rD .gnileef saw eh tnemeticxe eht mlac ot
",em wollof ,enoyreve ,thgirlA"
,ecnelis fo tnemom a saw erehT
,gniog saw kcurt eht hcihw ta deeps eht htiW .selim rof dnA
.pu og uoy ,maertsnwod revir eht wollof syas ti fI .htuos og uoy
,loohcs eht ni eno tseggib eht saw enirevlow eht hguoht nevE
"…sdneirf tog ev'I
.noos uoy ees ll'I
.evom eh sa eciton ot mees neve t'ndid
,flesmih no ni gnilruc morf flesmih peek ot dah eH
.redloh puc a ni ti gnittup erofeb ti fo pis gnol a gnikat
.hcamots sih fo tip eht otni knis traeh sih gnikam ,prahs erew sdrow siH ".uoy
.llew sa gnidliub eht sdrawot kcab gninnur stluda eht fo sdnuos eht raeh dluoc ekalB
,gnikaeps detrats yeht ecnis emit tsrif eht roF
.nwo sih no nur ot nageb dna deddon eH
.yas ot detnaw eh tahw tuoba gnikniht
.niaga revo dna revo ecnad dna gnos siht enod dah rotcod eht ekil ,sredluohs sih fo gurhs evissimsid a saw erehT .xof eht no deworran seye ,dias eh
.gnorw etad eht nettog evah thgim dranreB taht yrrow ot gninnigeb saw ekalB dna ,dne
.noitats sag eht ot noitaler ni saw eh erehw ot
.meht tuoba saw noitasrevnoc eht taht dnatsrednu dluoc eh dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.hguorht pils tlef eh yhtapmys eht fo yna tel t'ndid tub ,detats eh
,elims llams emas taht mih gnivig
,ni gnittis saw eh deb eht ffo tog eH
eh nehT .teef sih ot depmuj dna tfel eh erehw pukcip saw od dluoc eh llA
yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.mih rof gnikool ytlucaf eht fo eno eb dluoc dessap taht rac yna taht gniwonk
.thgis eht ta gnikwag lla snaidraug dna srebmem ytlucaf eht ,esruoc fo dnA
.ecaps eht hguorht ees ot gniyrt ,niaga dehsup ekalB ".ereh
,dnuora dekool esuom ehT
.pils ruoy tegrof t'noD
"?em gnipleh uoy er'yhW"
nehw noitats sag eht otni gniog redisnocer ot ydaer tuoba tsuj saw eh dna pu dekcol erew owt tsrif ehT
.dleif eht sdrawot gnivom stneduts ynam oot eb ll'erehT .oN"
.ria eht otni pmuj eht ekam god eht was eh sa kcab srae
pot eht raelc neve t'ndid toof sih tuB
.elit yreve neewteb kcarc yreve naelc dna seenk sih no nwod teg mih edam yehT
",uoy fo duorp os m'I
”?htaP gnidiuG tuoba wonk uoy d’woH“
pu mih tpek dnim sih ,fo yad eht tser s'thgin doog a teg ot gnitnaw etipseD
.tuo dnuof neeb d'yeht erus syob htob
.esirprus elttil a htiw pu tnew sworb s'ohw ,enirevlow eht ot denrut eH
.stnerap sih htiw gnikaeps nilloC fo thguoht eht ta daerd htiw deinapmocca saw ti tub ,tuo dnuof neeb t'ndah eh taht gniwonk ,feiler fo tnemom devil-trohs a saw erehT ".mih
,pleh ot elba eb thgim taht sdneirf emos tog ev'I
.eil dluohs eh fi gnirednow ,dnoces a rof ti tuoba thguoht eH
.epacse rieht no sevlesmeht etalutargnoc dna rehto hcae dnuora smra parw dluoc yeht nehT
,won gninnur trats retteb uoY
,stifeneB htiw sruF desaeler yltnecer eht ni skrow sih dnif nac uoY
,tey retaews elygra tseilgu eht gniraew
",gniksa rof sknahT .yaw eht yb ,doog neeb s'tI
,mih ta regnif a detniop kcirtapztiF .rD ".deppart er'eW
.srepap sih htiw taes eht fo tuo gnitteg
.siht ot dne na tup ot pael ralimis a ekam ot deirt yksuh eht ,daetsnI
.raf siht nettog ydaerla d'eh retfa ni mih nrut thgim yeht fi ,esrow rO
.koohs eh sa ylthgit mih gnidloh ,mih dnuora smra sih depparw ekalB
dnuorg eht ot toof sih detnalp eh sa dehctaw ekalB
.ton naht lacirotehr erom tlef noitseuq siH ”?uoy evagrof eH“
.trapa llaf edacaf sih tel eh taht moor sih edisni kcab yaw eht lla tog ekalB litnu t'nsaw tI ".taht
.ssarg eht otni talf gnillaf erofeb drawrof spets gnilbmuts wef a koot nilloC
.eunitnoc ot ti decrof nepo rood eht gnipeek
,hguoht lrans a otni gnitsiwt elzzum sih ees dluoc ekalB
htiw laed ot reisae erew syob owt eht taht dediced yksuh ehT
erutrot fo dohtem yna ekil rof
.tey kaeps ot ydaer saw eh ekil gnimees ton
.ecar a gnirud tsoob artxe taht flesmih evig ot dedeen eh nehw thgim eh yaw eht
.tuo gnilip nageb stneduts eht nehw ylredro dna ecin t'nsaw tI ".esaelp
.llew sa thguac neeb d'yeht gnizilaer ,was netram enip eht tahw ta tuo dekool syob rehto ehT
,yhs tsuj llef tI
.rood eht hguorht deklaw dna taes eht fo tuo pu tog eH
.ay ecudortni annaw I fi rednow ot gnitrats m'I tub
.pal sih neewteb nepo koob txet a tpek eH
.detcelloc dna mlac sa ffo flesmih yalp ot deirt eh nehw neve
.wap a pu dleh ekalB
.laog sih gnirebmemer osla elihw dnim ni meht peek ot deganam eh ,hguoht wohemoS
,dettimda eh tahw rof leunammE etah ot detnaw ekalB
”,pmhM“ a evag tsuj leunammE
,gnilbmert doots nilloC
.mih morf noitcaer a ticile ot desoppus saw taht fi erus t'nsaw ekalB dna ,dias eh
kniht neve dluoc ekalB erofeB
.nepo gnuws srood elbuod eht
",emoh og ot tnaw I
.tuo gnar mrala na ,dedne ssalc eht erofeb setunim eviF
,mih rof t’nsaw ti fi ,llew sA
".ysae ytterp ti evah uoy ekil em ot smees tI .uoy rof erac eW
,elzzum sih no gnuh nirg kcis tahT
,tsixe ton seod ti dneterp ot suounegnisid eb dluow tI
,dedne sessalc retfa yletaidemmI
.elzzum sih no elims lufyalp a tpek tub ,seye sih dellor kcirtapztiF .rD
,tib a rof dettahc yehT ".ekalB
.nilloC fo yaw eht ni teg ot hguone tsaf gnivom ton tub
s'yksuh a was eh litnu t'nsaw tI
.meht retfa gnitnirps nageb dna
.seye sih dellor nilloC dna ,dias eh ",stnerap ruoy s'tI"
"?meht daer ot gniog yllaer uoy erA"
.htap sih ni yltcerid delppot dial eert egral A
.ti otni lla rieht gnittup erew yeht tub
.mih ot pu thguac llits dna ylefas revo delwarc neve evah dluoc eh ro
.maercs dna nwod kaerb ot tnaw mih gnikam
,dehcnelc tsif siH
,lla ti fo esion eht revO
,hguoht og tel t'ndid eH
.moor eht ni nilloC gnivah rof tsuj elbuort ni teg dluoc yeht dna thgin eht ni etal gnitteg ydaerla saw ti esuaceb dalg saw ekalB
.yllacidolem mih dednimer eh
.ytud lairotinaj fo keew a sevlesmeht denrae tsuj enoemos kniht I" ,dias eh dna
.pleh ruoy rof lufetarg yllaer m'I .yrros m'I"
.tfel sih ot tuc tsaf a did ekalB dna edis sih yb thgir welb esuom ehT .tub
.esahc siht dne thgim taht giwt ro kcor yna gnilaecnoc ylerab
.ti no tuo tca ot detnaw eh dna ,tug s'netram enip eht fo edisni denruhc erif A ".syob
.uoy hcaet eW .uoy deef eW"
,noitcerid yreve ni nar yehT
.seert eht sdrawot elzzum sih gnitniop dna mra s'netram enip eht ffo gniworht ,dias nilloC ",oG"
.thgirpu peek ot deirt eh sa deeps gnisol
,htrof dna kcab daeh sih koohs nilloC
,ti fo thgis eht tA
.mih fo daeha dnuorg eht ta kool ot gnivah ,t'ndluoc eH
.dias reve elims ekaf sih naht erom ekops worb denepeed siH
.sraet gniwolf ydaets eht ffo gnipiw
:wohs ot sdnetni yrots siht sa ,sniamer epoh tuB
.ediw tuo gnidaerps stneduts rehto nezod a tuo ekam dluoc eh
.thgir t'nsi sihT
nilloC ",mih etah gnikcuf I"
rehtona eno tsniaga meht gnikcilf ,swalc sih ta dekool eH
.relooc eht rof dnuora dehcaer neht dna
,deil eh ",dab taht t'nsi cisum ehT
,loohcs eht fo ecnartne tnorf eht dessap yeht sa tsuJ
.yawa mih evig dluow
.ekalB sdrawot denrut eh sa pu gnikrep srae diletsum llams ,gnikahs deppots eH ".noos…ereh
ksed sih no reward a denepo rehto siH
,elims sselhtoot llams taht otni kcab dewollem nirg dekciw s'xof ehT .tsugsid ylnO
.ksed eht fo gel a tsniaga dekcik eh sa depmuj gnihctaw syob htoB
,tey tuo mih nworht t'ndah dna loohcs eht tuoba wenk knuks eht fI
…syug doog er'yeht ,daD ,oN"
.ria eht ni gnisiar wap a yb deppots saw eH "—
dluow doirep eht erofeb setunim net saw tI
.loohcs eht ot kcab dna secnef eht sdrawot gnidaeh
.evaw a ti gnivig dna kcats eht pu gnikcip
feiler dna raef ehT
.wodniw renid eht hguorht bac eht otni poh uoy waS"
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.niaga revo lla etapicitrap ot mih gnicrof kcirtapztiF .rD ekil tlef tI
.rood eht no wodniw elttil eht morf weiv fo tuo deppiks eh ,yletaidemmI
.rekcol a dniheb dih tub ,dworc eht morf yawa teg t'ndluoC .yrroS"
.lwarc a ta gnivom erew meht fo enon tub ,yb dessap sraC
.llac a deviecer eh nehw krowemoh revo gniog yltsom
.niaga knird ygrene sih fo pis a gnikat erofeb deksa eh
.evol fo gnivresed dna elbarenluv
".od ot deen I tahw wonk emmel tsuJ"
mih htiw epat fo llor a kcuns eH
deworruf worb sih
.em was enoemos kniht I"
.cinap elbisiv sih ni gninediw seye ,deksa dranreB "?ti dekcol yehT"
,taht ta deddon syob eerht llA ".ytpme
.syob rehto eht rof tneduts yralpmexe na eb ot uoy tnaw I dna
.citamard os eb t'noD .oN"
.daeh s'knuks eht fo kcab eht ta yltnetni gnirats
.yas ot gnihtyna evah t’ndid knuks eht
.niaga meht morf gniraeh ro gniees reven tnetnoc yletelpmoc saw eh ,tcaf nI
.leurc saw uoy ot deneppah tahw taht tpecca ot evah d'uoy
.taht ekil era srekcurt lla kniht uoy fi VT hcum oot gnihctaw neeb uoy
?taht od ot dewolla yeht erA"
,pu tilps teg ew esac ni tub
.doog neeb evah t'ndluoc gel dna toof sih ot did eh revetahW
.eerht eht gnihctaw dna nezorf
—ot tnatropmi os s'taht yhw wonk t'nod I
.owt eht neewteb gnihtemos wenk eh ekil
"?uoy ot did yeht tahw taht sI"
.enicidem nwo sih fo etsat a xof eht evig ot tub ,epacse eht rof tnemeticxe htiw tsuj toN
.lufepoh dednuos tsoM
.yob rehto eht ta worb sih worruf tub pleh t'ndluoc netram enip ehT
.denepo deirt eh eldnah driht eht
.siht fo tniop elohw eht s'taht dna ,thgir ton er'uoY"
.eseht evah ll'uoy
,ekalB gnidulcni ,tneduts yrevE
.kcen sih fo epan eht no htaerb sih leef yllacitcarp dluoc tub ,dneirf sih gnisahc deppots dah god eht llet dluoc eH
.ti gniod syob rehto eht dna nilloC was eh nehw tnemhsinup laer a ekil mees t'ndid seitud lairotinaJ
,dnuora gnidnats stneduts derdnuh a htiw ecnef knil niahc ehT
,dessih kcirtapztiF .rD ",od uoy ,seY
.draug eht dna mih neewteb ecnatsid lauqe emoceb dah dranreB taht ees ot kcab dekool ekalB .ni gnisolc saw meht gnisahc eninac eht dna dniheb gnillaf saw eh taht llet dluoc eh
.eromyna nur ot evah t'ndluow ekalB
.ereh degnoleb meht fo enoN .ssendnik dna ecneitap saw detnaw eh llA
.srood eht fo eno ta renroc a morf daeh sih gnikop ,sdnoces wef a detiaw ekalB
,ti dellik evah dluow yeht nehw erus neeb evah t'ndluoc eH
",yllautcA" "—ew dluoc os
.drawrof mih egru ot kcab sih no wap a peek ot dah netram enip eht dna ,yrujni sih htiw tsaf yrev gnivom t'nsaw nilloC
.tuo deppils ew wonk t'now yeht ,no gniog llird erif eht htiw tub ,denepo s'ti fi ffo og ot deggir s'tI"
,flesmih tuoba pu gninepo netram enip eht
neht dna hcae dranreB dna nilloC ot repap a dessap eH ".pu
.tsrow ta tsirw eht no pals a meht teg ylbaborp dluoc hcihw ,gniyduts tsuj saw won thgir revoc riehT
.ssenlufnis rof ecnatneper tuoba lla erew segassap ehT
.edis sih no erew yeht epoh ylno dluoc eh
.sdon llams ni nwod dna pu daeh sih gnibbob ,dias eh
.snoitseuq sih lla derewsna dna pu tpek eh tub
dluow yeht ,gnineve gniwollof ehT
.hgis gnol a tuo tel
.ecar traeh sih edam retfa dessap taht etunim yrevE
.mih dniheb rood eht desolc dna
.sdrow sih ni yoj fo tol a eb ot mees t’ndid erehT
.morf derevocer eb neve eb nac tI
,roolf tserof eht fo tsom derevoc egailoF
.sdneirf sih htiw saw eh dias etammoor sih tub ,moor sih llac ot deirt I
.retaeb efiw nrow llew a dna
,redluohs sih no wap a dah kcirtapztiF .rD
.evisserpmi yrev ,woW"
.gnivom sregnif sih peek ot repap eht no gnilbbircs tsuj
,mih rof devaw ekalB
.netram enip eht morf enohp eht gnikat
.ytisoiruc sih yfsitas ot tsuj fi
,tsehc sih ni doots traeh siH
.enil rehto eht morf emoc eciov a raeh ot elba neve ton srae prahs s'ekalB
.skool deirrow htiw rehto hcae sdrawot gninrut ekalB dna dranreB htob
,reve sa emit a sa doog sa saw tI
.setadpu erutuf rof
.elbraw ot nageb elims tfos s'xof eht ,ekops eh sA ".srehto
.denetsil eh sa nwod dna pu daeh sih gnibbob enirevlow eht
:rood a evoba srettel neerg ni ees dluoc eh ,yawllah eht otni daeh sih dekop eh nehW
.fles regnuoy sih fo erutcip eht ta kool ot detnaw eh ekil ,thgir sih ot ffo dekcilf seye siH ".citamard
.gninnur tpek tsuj dna
.esaelp ,enil ylredro dna eciN"
.msacras fo tnih on htiw suoires erew sdrow siH
ereht thgir nwod kaerb ot detnaw eh dna
.nem eht tsgnoma tsetsaf eht gnivom enilef eht
”.ereht teg I erofeb thgir ekam ot sgnorw attol elohw attog I kniht I ,hguoht eM“
",ecaf ym ot taht yas emoC"
.nwod daeh sih dna llams flesmih gnipeek ,daor eht ssorc ot luferac saw eH
.gnihtemos no elbmuts ot gnidneterp erofeb tsuj
,lwoh ro yrc ro tuohs t'ndid nam ehT
.sdrawkcab spets egral ot nageb eh sa dias eh
.retfa ni emac eno on nehw ytlucaf dna slegnA naidrauG eht morf raelc eht ni ylekil tsom erew yeht wenk eh ,etunim a retfA
.loohcs lufwa taht ot nos sih gnidnes
.thgiarts no daeh sih tup ot dah eh
.tey noitca fo nalp evisiced a ot gnimoc ton ekalB
,hteet dettirg hguorht tuo derettum eh ",kcuf
"?thgir ,pmac nosirp naitsirhc tihsllub taht morf er'uoY
yletaidemmi pu teg t'ndid enirevlow ehT
.stnerap sih morf ytilauxes sih gnidih ecnis neeb d'eh naht eerf eroM
.oot taht detah eH
,ysae oot elttil a tlef tI
edisni depmuj ekalB
.ti ot hturt yna dah ev'thgim taht dias kcirtapztiF .rD gniht ylno eht tuoba thguoht neht dna ,dias eh ",thgiR"
ti otni redluohs sih tup eh ,dnoces tsal eht tA
.hteet sih tirg ot ton gniyrt ,dias eh ",rehtegot meht weiver dluow ew dias uoY"
"?thgir ,ereht attuo ay tog I ,yeH .dik eiggib on
.detaeper neht dna esuap dnoces evif a gnivig erofeb stsrub dnuor eerht ni gnar tI
.riahc sih no flesmih nesool ot gniyrt ,dias kcirtapztiF .rD "?tnew keew ruoy woh em llet uoy t'nod yhW
.slirtson sih hguorht hgis llams a evag leunammE
.nwod dna pu daeh sih gnicnuob ,dias knuks eht ",hcum sa derugif ,haeY"
.sdrawkcab ti gnippuc ,rae dednuor sih ot pu wap a detfil knuks ehT
.si ti sa dab sa tib yreve ton si ti taht ro
.enirevlow eht rof tiaw saw od dluoc eh llA
.flesmih niartser ot deganam tub ,tuo gnihtemos llac ot tuoba saw eh ekil dekool dna tsif a depmup enirevlow ehT ".tuo
.mih otno snrettap deroloc elib pu dekup tsuj enoemos ekil
.dnuorg eht tih ssa sih sa neve
.enog era srehcaet dna stneduts eht fo tsom erus er'ew litnu ereht tiaw
,lleW" .detrats neve ti erofeb revo lla saw nalp eht ekil
.mih ta detniuqs dna s'nam redlo eht teem ot ezag sih denrut ekalB ".nwo
.efas saw eh wonk d'eh dna
.wol gniyats dna ni gnidnelb
.yaw eritne eht meht retfa gnisahc saw redluob a ekil leef ti edam yteixna eht tub
,ylsselerac cisum yrtnuoc sih detsalb tsuj eH
.ytpme era sllah ehT
.kcab flesmih dloh ot dah eh wenk tub ,ecar a erofeb tsuj teg d'eh gnileef emas eht saw tI
.trapa raf oot ton yllufknaht
.rood eht rof degrahc yob
.leunammE rof yltsom saw ti fi neve
.moor gnitiaw eht otni dna eciffo eht tuo deklaw eh sa
.tseretnisid fo wohs a no tup dluoc eh fi sa
.elituf si ypareht noisrevnoc ,yletamitlU
,raelc si tsaoc eht nehW
,esuom eht no ecnuop dluow eh sa noos sa dna egatnavda eht dah god ehT
,pleh rof ksa dna edisni og ot saw thguoht tsrif siH
.mih naht regnuoy shtnom wef a yllautca saw eh
elzzum sih ffo tekcaj mined eht gnillup
dezilaer eh taht evird eht ni ruoh na litnu t'nsaw tI
.eson sih ot esolc dehctiwt pil sih tub
gnihtyna od ot deracs oot tsuj saw ro dias eh tahw draeh dranreB rehtiE
,lausu naht gums erom demees elims siH
.dnuorg eht otni nam eht gnikacnap
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a ,levon a gnitirw si
.reviecer eht no ti gnimmals erofeb enohp eht fo enot eht ot gninetsil
.tuo erugif ot ekalB rof drah oot t'nsaw dekcolnu saw bal ygoloib eht erus gnikaM
egral eht erofeb sdnoces evif rehtona detiaw neht ,semihc eerht eht rof detiaw nilloC
,nam gnuoy trams a hcus er'uoY
.gniod saw eh tahw eulc a dah evah t'ndluow yeht derugif eh tub
gnihtemos ro wodniw a s'ereht ebyaM
.elzzum sih no elims reppihc ,yob noil eht deppets tuO .mih
s'leunammE fo kcab eht otni seloh nrub ot gniyrt deppots tsael ta eh tub
.kcirtapztiF .rD sdrawot thgiarts gnidaeh dna deeps pu gnikcip mih saw nilloC fo was ekalB gniht tsal ehT
.syad wef a rof ti dloh ot hguone thgit skeehc ttub htiw loohcs eht ni eno ylno eht m'I kniht I"
,dnoces a rof pil sih ta dewang eH .elzzum s'kcirtapztiF .rD fo tuo emac reve taht gnihtyna naht eniuneg erom tlef yeht dna
,ti tuoba kniht ot dah eh esuaceb yllaitrap
.pihsrow ta uoy was I"
.soahc erup saw tI .sepacse nwo rieht gnikam lla syob rehto eht rof nur ot gniyrt ,llew sa tuo gnidaerps saw ytlucaF
,dniheb mih evael ot tnaw t'ndid eH
",hguorht meht tuP .em s'ti ,haeY"
.bal ygoloib eht otni edils ot mih rof ysae ti gnikam
evah dluoc eninac ehT
.rood eht tuo pmuj dna bac eht fo edis regnessap eht rof elbmarcs dluoc eh erus saw mih fo traP
.kcab sih gnikorts ,dias eh ",won nalp eht gninodnaba ni tniop on s'erehT
tahW" ,deksa neht dna deddon dranreB ".evom
.elohlleh taht fo tuo enoemos gans ot sepoh ni dekcolnu srood eht evael dna pots taht ta kaerb a ekat ylno I ,dlot eb hturT"
gnittup dna revo gnihcaer ekalB ,stops degnahcxe syob owt ehT
,kcuF" .ti ot hgual a fo krab eht dedda neve dna
,og ot erehw wonk I"
.depacse eb nac ti
.dnuos a gnikam ton ,llits deniamer eh tub ,denediw seye s'ekalB
,syob rehto dna ffats morf tnemtaert lufwa eht ron mih sllet kcirtapztiF .rD seil eht etarelot ot gnitnaw toN
ti fo llA .dessap taht etunim yreve elim rehtona saw eh derugif eh
,eno dettops a ,knuks a saw tI
.ydob sih fo ecrof lluf eht htiw tixe eht otni dehsams dna
,puorg tsegral eht dniheb yats ot elba saw ekalB
.rialf ot nageb slirtson sih sa detfil daeh sih peek ot dah eH
,ria eht ni gnuh sdrow esohT ".ti ekil sdnuoS"
.sedis sih ta naidraug drapoel a dna yksuh eht was ekalB
,gol eht ta gnigrahc llits ,yksuh eht ees dluoc eH
,dias nam eht nehw dessimsid saw tahT
,dedda leunammE ,liob ot nigeb yllaer dluoc doolb sih erofeB
.nwod eciov sih peek ot gniyrt ,deksa eh
,daeh sih tfil ot delggurts draug eht sa rorroh ni dehctaw eH
,emit hcum taht evah t'nod ew dna hcraeser fo tol a did I"
.taht did eh fi daor eht fo edis eht no raems a pu dne ylbaborp d'eh dezilaer eh nehw evah dluohs ti naht regnol dnoces a ylbaborp
"?uoy era ,evael em tel annog reven er'uoY"
.erif no ecalp siht gnittes yllautca enoemos tuoba srumrum dna sehsuh erew erehT
ymedacA htaP gnidiuG ot kcab og ot decrof gnieb dna delgnaM
,erif ekil denrub tsehc siH
.kcab sih ot tog ekalB dna nilloC sa tsuj flesmih ot derettum eh ",tihS .tihS"
,ylsuonimo delttar ksed eht no enohp ehT
.raf siht teg em gnipleh rof sknahT“
"?gniog er'uoy erehw wonk uoy oD
.siht esol tonnac uoy tub
,tsehc rieht ni dleh straeh riehT
.niaga revo trats mih ekam d'yeht esle ro ksat yreve retfa ylsselwalf kcab meht taeper dna segassap eziromem ot dah eH
,depmuls sredluohs sih dna tirg hteet s'nilloC ".dworc
.taht wenk ydaerla uoy erus m'I"
.gol eht revo gnipparw ydob
.yadot gnittahc hguone dah ev'thgim ew kniht I" .ylkciuq rood eht gnikcolnu dna ksed eht dnuora gniklaw ,taes sih fo tuo tog kcirtapztiF
"?yltcaxe ,teg uoy ti si tahW
,gnituohs ,detaeper eh sa elzzum sih fo edis eht nwod gninnur ydaerla erew sraeT
,deksa eh ,flesmih pots ot
,dias eh sa deworran stils enipluv sih dna
.ylthgit ti dezeeuqs eh dna sdapmlap sih otni delruc sregnif s'xof ehT
,dnoces a detsal nalp tahT
.pils eht debbarg eh nehw ksed eht no wap sih demmals ekalB ".ffats
.ti draeh nam eht taht erus saw eh dna
".yaw eht yb ,leunammE s'emaN
,dessih ekalB ",tihS"
.elbissop sa llits sa niamer ot elims sih gnicrof saw eh ekil
.nur ot ecnahc gnithgif a dranreB evig tsael ta ot draug eht rewoprevo thgim eh thguoht eh sa gnisnet selcsum
,dessih netram enip eht ",nilloC" .feiler fo hgis a tuo tel ekalB dna dranreB htob dna weiv otni deppop elzzum enirevlow A
.rof gnitiaw saw eh tahw ta kcab kniht ot dah netram enip eht ,deksa eh "?lleW"
.flesmih stnerap sih gnivigrof enigami ot ekalB rof elbissopmi demees tI
.htxis eht erofeb syad elpuoc a ,nilloC dna dranreB ot denialpxe ekalB
.teef sih ot pu nilloC gnipleh
,mih evol ot uoy stnaw doG ,deruc eb ot uoy tnaw stnerap ruoY
.epacse na rof snalp eht nageb dna
.krow fo tol a enod ev'uoY
.bos a hguorht delworg nilloC ",em hcuot t'noD"
.ytefas rof noitats bal a dniheb tpel yllacitcarp
dna deraor enigne eht litnu t'nsaw tI
.nirg retsinis a htiw ksed eht morf kcab wap sih dellup kcirtapztiF .rD
.snoitavreser sih emacrevo ytisoiruc sih litnu ffo tup eh noitseuq a saw ereht ,hguoht noitasrevnoc eht tuohguorhT .fo trohs eb ot demees reven knuks eht hcihw ,sekoj sih fo emos ta dehgual neve eH
.daor eht dnuof eh erehw tniop eht litnu pu neve
,skcurtimes fo wor eht sdrawot denrut eh ,daetsnI
"?thgirla ,drah neeb s'tI"
,tuohs enoemos fo dnuos eht draeh eh
"!tixe ycnegreme na s'tI
.tnemhsinup rehtruf diova dluoc eh os tsuj denaelc eh sa dnim sih ni taeper ot dah eh seiticorta ydroW
.llew sa mih ytip ot gninnigeb saw tub ,mih detah ekalB ".bmun
,edis eht ot kcilf seye s'netram enip eht edam tahT ".ti
.eman nwo sih yas neve ot diarfa oot ,deksa eh "?olleH"
;rehtie ti revo lwarc ot pots t'ndluoc eH
.rewsna na gnitcepxe yllaer ton
.eldarc sti ffo enohp eht debbarg dna deb sih  ffo teg ot egaruoc eht tog ekalB taht gnir htruof eht litnu t'nsaw tI
,dennuts saw xof ehT
fi ro no gniog llits saw llird eht esuaceb saw ti fi erus t'nsaw eh tub
.mih teg dluow god eht dna nwod wols d'eh ,thgir ro tfel tuc eh fI
,edis derujninu sih htiW
,loohcs eht morf selim saw eh ekil tlef esahc ehT
"?taht saw tahw ,yrroS"
.taorht s'xof eht fo tuo emac elkcac a fo gnihtemoS
,mih rof doog saw tahw wenk kcirtapztiF .rD fI
,kcurt sih edisni kcab tog eh revenehw taht did tsuj nam eht fi derednow eH
.ereh dnuora sdradnats ytefas tuoba erac yllaer yeht kniht t'nod I"
.yllautneve meht ot teg ll'I erus m'I tub ,od ot krow fo tol a tog ev'I"
.dluoc eh sa tsaf sa ffo koot dna yksuh eht ot resolc saw eh woN
.eciffo sih ot tog eh nehw ydaer erew hcraeser fo skcats siH
.annaw t'nod uoy fi ereh pu emoc ot evah t'nod uoY
.mih pleh ot gnilliw eb dluow ohw erus t'nsaw eh tub
.enirevlow eht dnuora smra sih gnipparw
,deksa kcirtapztiF .rD "?hO"
",retteb tog uoy litnu uoy kcohs dna sedortcele htiw pu uoy parts ot desu yehT .relluF .rM ,tuoba gniklat m'I tahw wonk uoy erus m'I ,hO"
.nepo welf rood eht dna pans a saw erehT
,renroc eht denrut ekalB sA "!ti rof kaerB"
.bac eht fo flah kcab eht ni detseretni mees neve t'ndid
”,yllautneve ereht tog ew tub ,thginrevo neppah t’ndiD .evah sih dna miH“
.riaffa tnasaelp yrev a t'nerew sllac eht taht wonk ot hguone llew wenk eh tub ,ecno ekalB dellac ylno dad dna mom nwo siH
.dednuofbmud sa tsuj erew slegnA naidrauG eht tub
.ssalg decrofnier eht hguorht raelc seert eht fo swodahs eht
.gol eht revo tpel dna
",eciov ruoy raeh ot doog oS .relluF .rM ,hA"
,kcohs otni gniog yksuh eht gnissentiw saw eh fi erus t'nsaw ekalB
,tuo llac ot elba saw eh taht ,pu gnitoob tsuj saw daeh sih ni retupmoc eht ekil ,kcilf srae
.mutnemom egnahc ot mih gnitcepxe ton drapoel eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
".uoy xif ot boj ym s'tI
,etal saw ti ,rewsna sih htiw pu emac eh emit eht yB
.ylnepo deirc eh sa redluohs sih gnikorts ,edis s'enirevlow eht ot pu emac dranreB
dna rehtegot sregnif sih gnissorc erofeb yawa meht deffuts ylkciuq dna ksed sih fo edis rehto eht no reward a pu denepo eH
.tihs emos ro raewrednu emos htaenrednu ylbaborp ,ereht kcab relooc a s'erehT"
,noitcivnoc htiw dias eh dna sliated tsal eht tog eh sa deppop selkcunk siH
.devivrus eb nac tI
.meht neewteb derahs gniwonk a dna
ll'eW .dekcolnu era srood eht erus ekam ll'I dna mrala erif eht gnirud otni pils ot ysae s'tI
.sdnoces evif rof gnisuap erofeb emihc eltsihw eerht taht gnivig
.ekalB s'eman yM .leunammE ,iH"
.raef tsrow sih was eh
.decnivnoc eb ot gnideen ton ,netsil ot gnilliw naht erom saw enirevlow ehT
?ti htrow eb modeerf dluoW
.tniop taht ta imes eht pots ot leunammE detcepxe eH "!drah neeb s'tI"
.llah eht fo edis rehto eht no pu enil enirevlow eht gnihctaw
.yako saw tI .haeY"
.sbac eht rof seldnah eht gniyrt nageb eh tub
.rekcurt eht ees ot hguone tsuj
!kcuf taf uoy ,ecaf ym ot taht yas dias I ?em raeh uoy diD"
.gnitiaw saw tixe ycnegreme eht erehw llah eht nwod
,ymedacA htaP gnidiuG ta devirra d'eh ecnis emit tsrif eht roF
,raewrednu fo elip a rednu ti dnuof eH
.mih hguorht gninnur saw stlov dnasuoht a ekil gnisluvnoc nageb dna hteet sih neewteb eugnot sih kcuts neht dna dias eh
.mih ta kcab daeh sih koohs ekalB
.syaw owt tnew snoisses eseht ezilaer t'ndid I"
.rewsna na wonk ot gnitnaw ton fo tliug gnibbats taht tog eh nehw gnisuap ,deksa eh ”,leunammE“
.yaw eht fo tuo pets dna nepo ti peek tsuJ"
.ti ekat yletaidemmi t'ndid ekalB tub
,dias eh ",siht detapicitna evah t'ndluoc I neve tub
hsub a dniheb morf tuo pmuj dluow dranreB taht depoh eh ,elihw eht llA
.mih ees ot dalg tsuj ,yltsoM .tiaw ot gnivah rof regna ni yllaitrap
,dias eh sa elims sih deniatniam eH
.ytinutroppo eht ssim ot tnaw t'ndid eh tub
mih otno gnidloh
.yltnetni erom dias dna htrof dna kcab daeh sih koohs ekalB
.ti tuoba ynnuf saw gnihtemos ekil dne eht ta eugnot sih gnikcilc ,dedda eH ".zzzzzzZ"
.noos…ereh fo tuo teg annog er'ew ,naem I .oN"
,seye s'ekalB otni pu dekool enirevlow ehT
,noitcerid yreve morf ni gnimoc nageb stneduts rehtO
.sehtolc eht htaenrednu gnidih erew yeht timda ot enoemos teg ot kcirt a ro flesmih ot dlot eh ekoj fo tros emos tsuJ
",epacse ycnegreme na s'tI" .tixE
.edisni dehsur dranreB dna ,niaga pu denepo rood eht ,retal etunim a naht sseL
,kcab srae sih dedlof ekalB
.eromyna loohcs eht fo senifnoc eht ni t'nsaw eh taht dezilaer eh
hctulc em dah yehT"
.mood rieht ot dna ssenredliw eht otni tuo sdneirf sih gnidael eb thgim eh taht deirrow eH
?relluF .rM .ooh-ooY"
?edistuo er'ew ecno tuoba
.enif saw keew yM"
.won ti teg I kniht I"
"?nam kcuf eht tahw
,degdod yeht redluob dna eert yreve htiW
.erow ylsuoivbo os eh tliug eht rof noitadilosnoc thgils eht ,dias ekalB
,nilloC ,skeehc ssa ruoy neewteb ti dloh ot evah uoy fi erac t'nod I
,eyA" .ti ees dluoc ekalB erus ekam ot daeh sih gnitlit ,taht ta delims leunammE ".pleh
.seiduts elbib ni gnittis erew stneduts rehto eht elihw serohc fo tsil gnol a nevig dna
.feiler tlef tsomla eh dna
.meht fo htob neewteb kool esnetni na derahs ekalB
.eerf saw eH .erac t'ndid eH
.txen eht dniheb dray a saw eh litnu
,sdneirf sih rof tseb eht depoh eh hguohT
.tekcop sih ni ti gnittup dna ylthgit ti gnidlof ,ti koot dranreB
,em ot elohssa elttil a eb nac uoy ,kooL"
.noitats sag eht ta kcab kcuts neeb llits evah dluoc eh
,deksa eh "?ecin gnihtemos od yug a t'nac ,dik tihS"
.wap a pu dleh nilloC sa ffo flesmih tuc eH "—
.mra sih gnidloh enirevlow eht ,ezorf dranreB dna nilloC
.did uoy krow hcum woh wenk I erofeb saw taht ,llew ,seY"
.redluohs sih no tesdnah eht htiw gnitiaw
,teehs tsrif eht debbarg ekalB ".krow
.sedis sti ta srepap fo kcats eht gnibbarg dna ni gninael
rof denepo rood eht erofeb gnol tiaw ot evah t'ndid eH
,tuo meht deppir eH
.moorhtab eht ni dranreB depmuj taht mih saw ti wenk eH
,dehsinif saw eh nehW
,tlahpsa gnidniw eht morf ecnatsid doog a tpek ekalB
.desserpminu derats ekalB
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.evom ruo ekam ll'ew nehw s'taht
,mih revo hsaw ot nageb
,dias neht dna ti ta dekool nilloC
.hgis detarepsaxe na tuo gnittel erofeb ria fo htaerb gnol a ni dekcus kcirtapztiF .rD
.s'nilloC ot esolc elzzum sih gnipeek ,repsihw a ni dias ekalB
.part etarobale na t'nsaw siht epoh saw od dluoc eh llA
",tuo uoy teg annog er'eW"
,knuks eht ecaf dluoc eh os flesmih denrut eh ,noitisop elbatrofmoc erom a otni gnitteG
.eye s'xof eht ta yltcerid taps eh sa drawrof ti tsurht dna kcab daeh sih dellup eh nehT .don prahs a evag ekalB ".ytud
,dluoc eh sa ylihtlaets sa dna ylkciuQ
?dnoces a rof xaler dna kcab tis tsuj ew t'naC .ysaE !haow ,haoW"
.rehcaet ruoy dniheb yatS"
.ruf nwo sih fo tuo pmuj ot ydaer erew senob sih ekil tlef eh dna
.ti revo lla gnitirw htiw segap elpuoc a ffo dewohs dna koob txet sih fo kcab eht ot deppilf eh nehT
.kcab sih no swap gnittup dna dnuorg eht ot nwod gnitteg ,edis sih sdrawot dehsur ekalB dna naorg a tuo tel eH
.raf yrev teg ot gniog t'nsaw eh ,gnivom saw nilloC yaw eht htiW
,edisni spihc fo sgab elpuoc a erew erehT
,mih tsniaga thgiew lluf sih werht enirevlow eht
.keehc sih tsniaga mih gnittih
,ylpmis dias ekalB ",ereh m'I ,haeY"
.ereht thgir tuo mih kcik dna daor eht fo edis eht ot revo llup ot mih detcepxE
.taes dna roolf eht revo lla gniyl sehtolc was dna bac eht fo noitrop kcab eht otni dekool eH
mih fo egrahc ni ffats ehT
,pu tnew wap s'enirevlow ehT
,rekcurt eht ,yllufknahT
,eerht eht rof hsad dam a nageb htoB
,noitasrevnoc eht ni esuap gnol a saw erehT
.srepap eht ta gnitniop erofeb taes sih gnikat ,ksed eht dnuora deklaw xof ehT
,dlot saw eh sa did ekalB
,eno raf a t'nsaw airetefac eht ot pirt ehT
,flesmih deraperp eH
.elbmert ot nageb ydob elohw siH
,tnecs eht morf tros emos fo knuks a
”.nos ym ees oT .gniog er’ew erehw s’tahT“
,yaddim noitats sag eht ot tog ekalB
,gniyas erofeb redluohs s'yob rehto eht degguls dna pu gnurps eH
.egrahc koot ekalB dna
.stsrub eerht esoht ni gnimihc mrala eht fo dnuos eht ot gninetsil
,seigolohtna gnimocpu
.seldnah rood eht nwod gnipiw emit artxe koot eh ezilaer ot gnimees ton ffats eht
.nam redlo eht yb dias eman sih raeh ot gnikcohs saw tI ".ekalB
.wap s'knuks eht ni ti gnittup erofeb tuo ti dellup dna nac eht dnuof eh tub
,wodniw eht ot deregnil seye siH .etal
.mih etagivan ot stuocs yob fo raey elgnis a no yler ot evah t'ndid eh taht hguone mih dediug daor eht taht lufknaht
.tnelis yltsom gniniamer llits elihw dluoc yeht sa kciuq sa devom meht fo eerht lla ,raelc saw tsaoc eht wenk eh nehW
,niaga gnihtyna yas t'ndid ekalB ".tihs
.lla ta fi noos pu gnitteg eb ot gniog saw eh ekil kool t'ndid eh dna
.tihs su evig srepoort yna esac ni tup deyats uoy fi tseb ylbaborp s'ti ,yllautcA
yllautneve tub ,nwod mih wols t'ndid tI
?uoy htiw ereht zeuqsaV .rM sI"
.dnoces a elim a ylbaborp
.deppord gnieb llac enohp eht fo enil talf eht raeh dluoc ekalB dna deppots eH "—
.dnim sih mlac ot hguone saw ssenevisiced eht yllufknaht tub
,hguoht desiar erew srae s’knuks ehT
.ti dnuof yllanif eh ,erofeb ot ssecca dah reven dah eh loohcs eht ni stops gninaelc syad wef a gnidneps retfa ,hguone erus dnA
,sdneirf tsesolc owt sih tsurt ot elba ylno gnieb fo shtnom retfA
.ti sdrawot yltcerid egrahc ot dah eh ,daetsnI
,deralf slirtson s'kcirtapztiF .rD .sdrow
.srehto no detcelfni reve ev'uoy ytleurc eht lla tnorfnoc ot evah d'uoy
.ni detepmoc reve d'eh ecar yna naht redrah gnidnuop traeh sih
,ecin erew sthguoht esohT
.mih no ni esolc ot nageb enirevlow egral eht sa gnilkcub sgel
.pils eht revo gnilbbircs dna gum sih morf nep a gnillup ,dias eh ",relluF .rM ,nam gnuoy thgirb yrev a er'uoY"
.saw keew ym woh em ksa d'uoy nehw s'taht ,yllamroN"
.tuo yaw rehtona dnif ot evah annog er'eW .edis rehto eht no gnihtemos ro kcoldap a s'ti kniht I"
”.ffopord a edaM .ecno ereht neeB“
.etelpmoc t'nsaw ti tub
.tsrif ta ti detah eh thguoht ekalB dna
.niaga teehs pot eht debbarg eh sa detseretnisid ylper
,oot bal eht otni og mih was stneduts emos demussa eH
,tnirps dam a edam eh
.erofeb ekam mih nees t'ndah eh taht noihsaf tnayobmalf a ni daerps smra siH
eht morf flesmih dleihs ot gniyrt saw eh ekil kcab dedlof srae siH
,ksa dna dnuora nrut ot eno eht saw eh taht ,enituor os saw tI
.saw ti yhw ees dluoc eh ,noitisop eht ni eno eht saw eh taht woN
daor eht ffo ylno saw noitnetta siH
,daor taht nwod og uoy fi dnA
.sevren eht ffo evats ot sguh gnitrap emos htiw retfa yltrohs moor sih rof tfel enirevlow eht dna dehgual yehT ".syad
,eno siht piks ot eerf leef esaelp neht
,detcepxe eh naht reittahc saw knuks ehT
,derats tsuj daetsni tub
.sruoh rof neeb t'ndah eH
.ria edistuo dloc eht rof gniraperp fi sa tsomla gniltsirb ruf
,deb eht ot mih del syob htoB
.ydaerla noitseuq eht wonk thgim eh ekil gninetsil
,tsenoh gnieb htrow saw ti neht
.spsag dellif-tons neewteb niaga revo dna revo detaeper
.tsehc sih ni gnidnuop ylbisiv traeh sih ,thgir dna tfel
.sehtolc eht lla rednu neve ,seerged net tsael ta deppord bac eht ni ria ehT
,nepo ti dekcarc eh sa dehctaw ekalB .dias eh ",sknahT"
.ydob sih morf deniard saw enilanerda eht taht won erew sgel dna liat sih eros woh gnizilaer ylno ,flesmih detsujda tsuj eH .daeh
.noitats sag eht fo noitrop renid eht no eye sih gnipeek
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.toof eno htiw ti revo eldruh flesmih dehctaw eh sa
noitats laidotsuc eht ot troper ot detcepxe saw eh
.riahc sih edisni kcab gnivom ydob niht
.resolc pets a tog yksuh eht
.kcab detlit daeh sih erofeb dnoces a rof
.neeb reve d'yeht naht reworran
.ymedacA htaP gnidiuG ta devirra d'eh shtnom eht ecnis neeb d'eh naht eerf erom tub
.gniog peek ll'eW .yako s'tI .yako s'tI"
".ymedacA htaP gnidiuG morf m'I ,haeY"
.rehtnaP emiT-lluF a ,ybigreK yb daeR
.bal ygoloib eht sesu eno on ,syadsendeW nO"
,deunitnoc dna teehs a htob meht dessap eH ".eseht
”,em ot tol a snaem tI
dnoces ecno mih fo tnorf ni teef wef a saw dranreB
,cibohpreeuq gninrecnoc yrots a fI
.roivaheb ym evorpmi ot tnaw t'nod I"
.mih ot kcab gnimoc imes eht tuo gnipmuj fo gnileef taht ,deksa eh
.skeehc sih ot yaw sti gnibmilc elzzum sih fo edisrednu eht gnola yerg htiw
.yawa seye sih kcud ot nrut sih saw tI
.eelg emos htiw deksa eh
.nwod tnew cisum eht fo emulov eht sa deksa revird kcurt eht
.enihcam esion etihw eht fo enord eht revo
.slirtson sih hguorht sekatni wollahs prahs gnihtaerb
.sdrawkcab era snoitcurtsni eht lla ,dnoceS
oot tuo pop dluow nilloC neht dnA
.syob rof loohcs ypareht noisrevnoc a ot tnes neeb dah ekalB ,emit tsaL
,doirep tsrif tuohguorht llA
,ecnartne eht tuo gnimoc erew snaidraug erom owT
",mih wohs ll'I neht dna ,ereh fo tuo teg ot erus eb ll'I ,haeY"
,snoitome gnitcilfnoc ni mih revo dehsaw
.mih fo tuo sraet eht fo tsom ,nwod dna pu tnew daeh egral siH
.rehtnaP emiT-lluF a
.dnopser t'ndid eH
,feiler fo hgis gnol a tuo tel ekalB
llits dnats ot demees emiT
.stsif otni swap sih dehctulc eh dna deltsirb ruf siH
,hguoht sdnoces wef yrevE
.ti kootsim ev'thgim knuks eht esac ni pu ti revoc ot gnirehtob neve ton
,yksuh dedniw ylerus eht fo daeha ecnatsid gnitteg flesmih tlef eh sa tsuJ
.ereh syob tsuj lla erew yeht taht ekalB rof rednimer a saw tI
.ni gnilwarc epoh fo revils eht tlef eh
.nwod gnireggats emac eh dna krab eht deppihc toof kcab sih nehT
,seitud gninaelc fo skeew owt ebyaM
,haey…haey…enif si gnihtyreve…daD iH"
.yletaidemmi ti gnitteg ton ,dias eh
.dworc eht tsniaga evom t'nac uoY
"?knird ygrene na em gnissap dnim uoY"
"?yadot 'uoY sevoL doG' oN"
,yltalf dias nilloC
.wols ot nageb etag s'nilloC tub ,seert eht rof gninnur llits saw dranreB
.snoitats bal fo wor eht sdrawot spets suoituac wols gnikat nosrep eno ylno saw tI .ni emoc evah ot snaidraug eht fo eno gnitcepxe ,gnicar saw traeh siH
.pu teg ot emit saw ti litnu rehtona eno otno gnidloh tsuj ,rehtegot deb ni thgin tsal eno derahs ekalB dna dranreB
.gnirettij morf sgel sih peek ot dah ekalB
.oot gninnur detrats evah dluow eh
.gninetsil saw eh taht srae sih fo noitcerid eht yb ees dluoc eh tub ,kcab daeh sih nrut t'ndid nam ehT
swap nwo sih otni erutuf sih koot ekalB
ria rof wam sih nepo t'ndluoc eh tub
.seriw dnuob ylthgit ekil delioc selcsum ,deriw tlef eH
tnemevom yna diarfa
tsrif ytilauxesomoh dna noisserped neewteb scitsitats eht revo og ot detnaw I ,oS"
.pu mih gnillup dna dranreB rof nwod wap a gnihcaer ,deddon nilloC ".og attog eW"
,sllac gniogtuo rof edam t'nsaw tI
,hguoht erofeb ekiL
.dliub ot nageb tliug eht sa neve
,flesmih esopmoc ot xof eht rof dnoces a koot tI
?rebmemer ,roivaheb tuoba s'tI
neht dna llaw a degguh eH
tsol eh snoitasrevnoc fo sraey eht gninigami saw eh fi derednow netram enip ehT
.ygrene s'ekalB fo lla deppas taht hcnurc ytsan a saw erehT
,tsrif teef sih ot tog ekalB
,regnol tib elttil a detiaw rekcurt ehT
.ecarbme eht ffo thgif ot ton tub
noitcerid a dekcip
.sdrawkcab llaf ot nageb eh dna ,gnitfihs retnec sih ,delbmuts sgel siH
,detpurretni kcirtapztiF .rD
:dnim ni peek ot sgniht owt s'erehT"
,deb sih ot tog eh sa noos sa tub
,tuo deirc ekalB ",pots t'noD"
.ylevissimsid deksa eh
.raf os dah yeht nalp eht htiw ni dellif saw nilloC "?tahW"
.elzzum sih tsniaga bmuht a depiw eh
dluoc eh sa tsaf sa gnivom saw esuom eht tub ,retsaf nur ot detnaw eH .mih dniheb teef elpuoc a dranreB htiw seert eht ot ydaerla
.deksa dranreB "?airetefac eht ot daeh tsuj ew ,llird eht gnirud oS"
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY  .emit rehtona
,dias dna gniyas t'nsaw eh taht sdrow eht wonk ot demees leunammE ,niagA  .on
.zzzzzzZ" .koohs ydob sih sa neve
evom ot nageb kcurt eht
,dranreB dna ekalB revo decnalg seye siH
.nwod dna pu daeh sih debbob tsuj knuks eht daetsni dna ,emac reven tI
.netram enip eht ffo worht ot gniyrt ,ydob sih koohs eH
fo tuo teg I nehw I esuaceb
.senob sih ni ehca na saw ereht ekil
.pu ti gninepo erofeb yllaudividni ffo lla meht kcip ot dah eh sa seye sih gnillor
.xof eht ot kcab neht dna
,htron og syas ti fI
,ni uoy nrut annog t'nia I ,netsiL"
,enola erew yeht fi dna
.sreksihw sih ffo gnignah sdaeb emos ,ruf sih nwod deppird sucum dna avilas ehT
.relluF .rM ,sgniht tnaw lla eW"
.syawla sa yltcefrep ti gnikam ,deb fo tuo tog ekalB
kcol eht fo kcilc elbidua eht ot gninetsil ,eciffo eht otni deppets eH
,snoitpo sih deredisnoc ekalB ".daehtihs
.emit fo tuo gninnur erew yeht tub
,daeh sih koohs ekalB
.rehtruf egdub t'ndluow ti tub ,niaga dehsup eH
.srenetsil emos ot gnibrutsid eb yam taht lairetam sniatnoc edosipe gniwollof ehT
.tpmetta eht rof detser llew eb ot evah
.hguorht thgil fo revils a tel ot hguone ylno tub ,denepo rood ehT
,detaehc gnieb fo esnes cisnirtni na saw erehT
,looc yalp ot deirt enirevlow eht sa hcum sA
,kcab eht hguorht meht del ekalB
,yrros os m'I .yrros m'I
esahc eht eunitnoc ot dnuora enog ylisae
.tuo maercs kcirtapztiF .rD fo llirhs dehctip hgih eht draeh ekalB "!potS"
.gnilbmurc saw ronaemed sih taht suoivbo saw ti
.regnarts modnar siht tsurt dluoc eh fi erus t'nsaw eh
.tixe eht ot yaw sih gnikam erofeb ylkciuq ffuts sih yawa gnittup ,dias rehcaet eht
.tnereffid tsuj ,rehtie revo t'nerew esohT
.gnorw gnihtemos gniod thguac neeb d'eh ekil
,trohs elzzum sih tpek ekalB
yas ot tnaw t'ndid eh esuaceb yltsom tub
,dehctiwt elzzum s'kcirtapztiF .rD
,ti fo pot eht deraelc hctorc siH
.dnoces tsal eht ta thguac teg ot ylno yaw siht lla tog eh ekil
,pu wap a dehcaer ylwols netram enip eht ,ksir a gnikaT
"?tsaoc tsew eht no stcatnoc tog uoY"
.sdrow sih ni gnilknirw elzzum ,dereens ekalB
.raeh ot stnaw rotpac rieht kniht yeht revetahw yas smitciv ekam ot si epoh nac ti tseb eht