.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.don a evag tub ,seye sih dellor ekalB
dniheb pu delwarc
.detnuts si ecalp sihT
.srecnad eht fo noitces evitca erom a ni dranreB was eh nehT
.hteet sih tirg eh dna ,esor kcen s'netram enip eht fo kcab eht gnola selkcah ehT
.gniht lluf eht em evig t'ndid uoy llet nac I
.tsugsid ni delruc elzzum sih sa gnitfil sreksihw ,denworf eH
.sdaeh rieht dewob ,dranreB gnidulcni ,stneduts eht fo tsoM
",ssenippah sa truh gnisiugsiD
.em eveileb ot evah t'nod uoY"
.ereh fo tuo teg ot dedeen yehT
.syob fo dworc eht ot og ot mih gnigru
"?nwod gnittis uoy er'yhW"
?snaidraug eht fo eno ti saW ?deneppah tahW"
,denoitnem dah dranreB ekil tsuJ
hsilgnE ni yasse na no edarg dab a tog I .haeY"
.snworf erow ohw stneduts rehto fo lufdnah a htiw gnola
,saw eh sa gib sa ,enirevlow eht nevE .mih ta kcab denworf syob htoB ".thginot
,yltalf dias dna segap erom wef a hguorht deppilf eH
.hteet sih neewteb ti dleh tub
taht leef tub pleh t'ndluoc ekalB
.sthgif yna otni nettog t'nevaH .dnabartnoc yna htiw thguac neeb t'nevah uoY
.dne eht litnu ti fo tsom ot noitnetta yap t'ndid ekalB
.od ot desoppus saw eh tahw gniod ti fo tsom tneps eh
.derahs yeht ssenesolc eht yojne tsuj dluoc eh taht gnihsiw ,hgis a tuo tel ekalB
",tenretni eht ot ssecca tnaw I"
.htmraw sih leef dna pu dnatS
.ni kcab gniworg fo tsdim eht ni hguoht ,tsap eht ni nwod demmirt neeb dah ti ekil dekool enam s'yob ehT
,detrats xof eht ",meht daer ot evah t'nod uoY"
.loohcs eht ta nuf sa ffo dessap yeht taht sgniht wef eht fo eno saw tI .htrof dna kcab deyaws yeht sa sredluohs revo smra ,cisum eht ot gnicnad nageb yehT
,levon a gnitirw si
pu swap reh dleh god ehT "!uoY sevoL doG
.redlof sih ot txen gum a morf nep a werd kcirtapztiF .rD
,strihs pu nottub eulb thgil emas eht gniraew lla syob yb dednuorrus
,mih ot txen tas ksed A
.nuf gnivah yleniuneg saw eh ekil dekool dranreB
.weiv ni deppets kcirtapztiF .rD ,xof der eht dna denepo rood eht ,retal dnoces A
.deciton esle enoyna fi ees ot dnuora gnikool dna daeh sih gnitfil erofeb dnoces a ereht doots tsuj esuom ehT
.thgim eh thguoht eh sa drah sa mih eborp t'ndid kcirtapztiF .rD
.nam gnuoy citamsirahc yrev a ekil mees uoY"
",tser eht fo erac ekat ll'I
,etoyoC triD yb ”nuR“
.kaerf gnikcuf a s'eH"
.dedaf reven elims sih tub ,detniuqs seye s'kcirtapztiF .rD ".ekil
.egdub t'ndid ekalB tub ,drawrof mih hsup xof eht tlef eH
.erofeb naht niatrec erom eciov ,deksa eh
.ecaf sih no esirprus saw demussa eh tahw thguac ekalB .ylthgils os reve detfihs ti
,mih htiw sreretupmoc eht gnirevocsid saw ehs ekil erew srewsna reH
.efas su peek ot ereh t'nera srehcaet dna snaidraug ehT
,nalp epacse na rof dnim ni sah ekalB tahw yltcaxE tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.edis eht ot daeh sih gnikcoc ,deksa nilloC "?ydaerlA"
,nilloC tuoba thguoht neve t'ndah eH ".ereh
.gnitnuad tlef troffe eht dna ,denrut ekalB
,ezorf ekalB ",tiaW"
"!su rof nos ylno sih pu evag eh ,hcum os su devol eH
.ti hctac ot gnithgif syob fo puorg a otni llab eht gniworht tsuj saw emag eht os
,gnidda erofeb ,noitcelfer rof tnemom a ,desuap ehs
mih eldarc ot tsuj
,eno siht piks ot eerf leef esaelp neht
.ti fo flah neve tuo gnillif ton ydob niht ,riahc sih otni dial xof ehT
.si edom otingocni tahw wonk neve t'nseod ksed eht ta toidi ehT
"?ydaerla dehsiniF"
rae sih tsniaga elzzum sih detser eH
.snoitasrevnoc laudividni tuo kcip ot mih rof hguone
noitasrevnoc yna delffum taht
.hgis llams a tuo tel
t'ndid eh ,tsaf os deneppah tI
.meht ta nwod gnicnalg dna flesmih sdrawot meht gnillup ,sregnif sih neewteb kcats eht debbarg kcirtapztiF .rD
,pu gnitteg yggorg saw eH
.mih otno gnidloh ekalB htiw t'ndluoc tub dnuora nrut ot gniyrt saw eh ekil
.loohcs eht fo tsom ekil
,dias kcirtapztiF .rD "?relluF .rM"
neewteb knil a s'ereht taht dnif seiduts taht rO
.wam sih otni ti gnikat dna faoltaem eht fo egdew a tuo gnittuc ,deddon ekalB
.saw eh erehw ezingocer t'ndid tsomla eh ,detcartsid os saw ekalB
.enot cidolem tsomla ,tfos a ni dias xof eht ",relluF .rM"
meht neewteb htmraw ehT
.ffo ti llup ot elba era sdneirf sih dna eh ton ro rehtehw dna
emas eht tnaw lla ew nehT"
.tcejretni ot deirt kcirtapztiF .rD seirtnasaelp yna yawa gnivaw netram enip eht
.ti ot flesmih detsujda eh dna
.dnim sih no deregnil llits taht seiromem eht ni pu thguac ,daeh sih detfil eH
.yllufesoprup os did eh dna esnetni saw ezag siH
drawrof gnihcaer ydaerla wap
pil sih no tup ot retaw dloc htiw gar a mih tog eH
,mih ta wap sih deoohs xof ehT
ereht eb ot detnaw taht stneduts eht neewteb swor ytpme wef a
.ekil ton thgim uoy srewsna dnif thgim I diarfa uoy era rO"
derahs yeht gnihtemos saw ti
,nam gnuoy suoiruc a er'uoy wonk I tuB"
,gnitiaw fo setunim neetfif retfA
.dworc eht htiw ni dnelb nac ew erehwemoS
,thgiarts t'nsaw nos rieht taht was yeht dnoces eht esuaceB
.tuo sthgil saw ti erofeb airetefac eht ni rennid derahs yehT
.enot gnizinortap sih htiw deppird sdrow siH ".si
.rehto hcae ot drow a dias yeht erofeb neve
htiw denrut ekalB ,deb eht ffo tog eh sA
.sdneirf sih ot eybdoog yas ot teg neve
.esuom eht ot elims a evag tub ,daeh sih koohs ekalB "?emoc annaW .sgel ym
.seye sih desolc dna noitisop ralimis
.tsehc s'netram enip eht otni gnillaf ,niaga nwod gnikaerb erofeb spil sih gnisrup ,elahni prahs a koot eH
.tnorf pu syob eht fo emos morf sreehc emos erew erehT
.ecalp siht denodnaba evah dluow ylerus eh ,dog a saw ereht fI
.emoh ta kcab airetefac sih t'nsaw tI
,swodahs eht ni meht dnuora lla gnidnats snaidraug dna srebmem ytlucaf gniees ,dnuora dekool ekalB
emit siht reduol ,erom ecno
.flesreh meht htiw railimaf yrev saw ehs ekil mees t'ndid ehs tub
.tsev retaews elygra eulb a ot denepo ti
was eh taht noil eht saw tI
.ecno loohcs dehctid reven eh taht rettam t'ndid tI
.emas eht lla teef sih ot gnitteg tub ,esnesnon emos gnilbmum
.syob rehto eht revo xelf ot tsuj
.nuf ro eniuneg yrev leef t'ndid tI
.yawa teg ot ydaer ,elddim eht otni deppets eh dna ,moor gnitiaw eht ni stneduts rehto on erew erehT
"?enola siht od t'nac uoY"
.dne eht ta enipluv llams eht saw ti wenk ekalB dna ,eno tsellams eht pu dekcip eH
.neht uoy fo htob rof seton ekat ll'I sseug I"
,renetsil ,derussa eb tuB
.ria eht otni hgih llabtoof eht worht dluow srotcurtsni myg eht fo eno elihw tnirps dna wor a ni pu enil dluow syob eht llA
,airetefac eht ni tops sih ot tog eh nehw tub ,edisni dedaeh eH
tuo ekahs ot deen tsuJ
.elzzum sih gnivael reven elims tfos taht ,dias eh
- si od nac uoy lla
.hcnul ot og t'ndid I yhw s'tahT
,sdrow reh detaeper ehS
.htaenrednu gnihtyna yawa gnivig ton ,dicalp ecaf sih tpek ekalB ,ciotS
.ti ot gniht tsesolc eht saw siht dna dleiF dna kcarT dessim eH
,strap ta desuap ehS
.staes rieht evael ot nageb syob erom sa
.evol sa nis gnisiugsid
.gniht tsal eno dedda eh
.tuo lla ti tel eh sa gnivom ton ,trihs sih otni yrc mih tel eH
"?syadawon eerht sa gnuoy sa sbuc no erac gnimriffa redneg wolla srehctub
.snoitpo laer yna nevig saw eh taht toN
,htaP gnidiuG ta degnahc t'ndah tibah tahT
.smrofinu eht hctam t'ndid taht sroloc raew ot dewolla eno ylno eht saw eh ekil demees tI
.ezag s'ekalB morf yawa dekool eh dna kcab dedlof srae egral sih ,ecnetnes sih dehsinif esuom eht sa noos sA ".tsaf
.delggij eciffo eht ot eldnah eht dna ,kcilc llams a saw erehT
.ni denael eh sa wol eciov
,sevooh sih tuo dleh dna meht neewteb flesmih degdew esroh ehT
.liat sih evoba tsuj
.saelp sih revo dias ekalB ",yako ,yakO"
,llird erif ,ylbmessa yna eziromem ot evah uoy ,egnuol ytlucaf eht ni er'uoy emit txen ehT .uoy deen I"
,elims mih edam tI
ll'tI" .ylnepo snoisses rieht derahs yllaer eno oN
.no denrut rotcejorp eht sa tsuj
,tuo dellac ehs esualppa dna cisum eht evobA
.egde eht no swap sih gnittup
,elzzum s'kcirtapztiF .rD kcab dellup nirg A ".elif
.hcraeser ym gniod neewteb spam ta kool ot elba neeb ev'I .adniK"
.ti eveileb ot demees enirevlow eht dna
.ereh morf raf oot ton snoitats sag wef A
.meht neewteb pag eht denessel eh sa
.ti desolc eh erofeb dnoces a flah rof nepo wam ,ereht kcuts tI
.peelsa saw dranreB erus saw eh litnu mih htiw deyats eH
.mih deppots dranreB tub ,knub rewol eht ot kcab evom ot ydaer saw ekalB .yako na dna don a evag esuom ehT
,pu tog gnittis llits erew taht syob eht fo tsoM
.ygolohcysp dna doG tuoba txet ni derevoc sevlehskoob lareves erew erehT
.kcirtapztiF .rD ot tisiv a yap ot flesmih nopu ti koot ekalB ,thgin ta yadnuS nO
.sretsnom emos morf yawa gninnur dna maerddim llits saw eh ekil ,elggurts llams a saw erehT
.ffuts dna sgniht
,reccos ot kcuts dranreB elihw
"?thgin ta peels hguone uoy gnivig ton yeht erA"
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.tnorf eht ni muidop a ta doots ehs sa dias rotsap rodarbal a ",emoc ,emoC"
.dexelf swalc sih erehw
,denepo elzzum s'kcirtapztiF .rD
,ezam a ekil tuoyal eht deziromem tub
.desolc htuom sih tpek dna ,flesmih deppots nilloC "—
.gnihtemos dellup eh ssel flesmih xaler ot dah eh taht hcum os tsiwt tug sih edam tI
,detcepsus ekalB ,semitemos dnA
.nuf yna gnivah t'nsaw eh gnizilaer erofeb dnoces a rof ti dehctaw ylno eH
,raeg evitcetorp yna evah t'ndid loohcs ehT
.emas eht lla citegrene tub ,esolc ton
.elihw a rof ereht dial yehT ".enola
eht fo tnorf ni smra fo aes a saw erehT
.egats eht no htrof dna kcab gnivom
"?recnad a toN ?epahs ruoy nI ?uoy ekil yob A
,evloser emos sa ti ekat ot demees dna deciton kcirtapztiF .rD
,eye sih thguac syawla taht
,tenretni eht esu ot dewolla saw eh nehW
.ylluf flesti dewohs reven taht nworf a fo tnih eht ees dluoc eh ,elims tfos taht dniheb dna ,mih ta ylkciuq pu dekcilf seye s'nam redlo ehT
.pal sih otni meht gnillup ,dias netram enip eht ",uoy knahT"
,nwo sih no pu tnew eH
,erehwesle noitnetta sih desucof eH
,trats eht ta elims mlac llams looc a dah kcirtapztiF .rD ".gniht
.sih otni ti koot yob rehto eht dna wap a tuo dehcaer eH .mih
.dleiF dna kcarT ni srennur rats eht fo eno saw netram enip eht taht rettam t'ndid tI
"?relluF .rM ,nommoc ni evah lla yeht tahw wonk uoy oD .sITS
sih ot deklaw neht dna
.ecnatpecca s’ti semitemoS
.radnelac eht eziromem tsuJ .nwod gnihtyna etirw t'noD .yrt ot evah eW"
.meht rof pu ti gninepo dna syek fo tes a htiw srood eht gnikcolnu ydaerla saw xof eht dna ecnartne eht ot tog htob yehT
.ylkciuq derettum eh
.detcepxenu eb ll'taht gnihtyna
.pirg sih ot erusserp erom dedda dna
.rewsna na ni detseretni flah kcab deilper eh
reeb fo pis a nekat dah hcum os reven eh taht rettam t'ndid tI
sthgiew eht htiw krow ot detpo nilloC
,moor nwo sih ot tog eh sa eybdoog devaw nilloC
.dneirf sih tsuj saw ti fi neve ,hcuot eht dnim t'ndid eH
.arbegla tsuj s'tI .haeY"
.hguoht raf oot toN
.rehto eht ot ecaf sih fo edis eno morf tilps elims a nehT
.elzzum sih no nrecnoc hcum t'nsaw ereht ,ksed sih no swoble sih htiw taes sih morf denael eh hguoht dna ,deksa eh
.eson sih morf sucum ydoolb emos yawa epiw ot desuap eh
.seiduts fo stxet deipocotohp saw tI
.yrotciv fo yrots a llits si siht
.rotsap eht fo dnuos eht revo daeh sih ni sciryl eht gniyalp
.daeh sih dewob dna mih ecaf ot denrut ,deppots ekalB ".ledom
",keew tsal uoy ees
,avilas htiw dellif elzzum sih ,laer os tlef tI
.sedisni eht nacs ot detrats dna
,dias dna mih morf ssorca owt eht ot pu dekool eh nehT
.ti gniod yllautca fo yhs tsuj saw eh ekil
,kcab wap sih dellup eh
.noitacidniv s’ti semitemoS
"?krowemoh ruoy xorex tsuj I fi eciton lliw rehcaet eht kniht uoY
.mih devom ylerab tI
.tnuoma tsethgils eht redluohs sih kcab dellup dna ,dias ekalB
.erac annog ton er'yehT"
.thginot kcirtapztiF .rD ees I"
.elbaliava eb dluow eh taht wenk eh tub ,xof eht gniees dedaerd eH
",ytud rotinaj em gnivig syawla s'eH .yug taht kcuF"
,gnidulcni erofeb ,eciov tfos emas taht htiw dias kcirtapztiF .rD ",yarts t'noD"
.sreksihw sih tsniaga delkcit rae s'tnedor eht ni ruf ehT
.tnih eht tog eh litnu sredluohs sih elffuhs ot dah eh ,peelsa llaf dluoc esuom eht erofeB
,mih dnuora lla seye sih gnikcilf xof eht ees dluoc eH
.retfa yltrohs emac peelS
.gnivah fo ecnahc rof gnithgif erew yeht tahw saw sihT
.thgir ton s'tI .enoemos llet ot evah ew ,lleW"
.nwo ruoy no daer ot hguone trams er'uoY
.htaerb gnineprahs sih htiw detcarter dna dehtaehsnu swalc sih dna
,loohcs a sa meht tiderc ylbissop dluoc taht scisab eht tsuJ
.emit siht nilloC ffo dezod eht htiw detaes gniyats dranreB
.gnileef eht dehsiler eh dna
,laidemer tlef esruoc hsilgnE sih nevE
,yaw taht mih dekil eh fi erus t'nsaw ekalB
.ni etapicitrap ot decrof erew yeht taht seitivitca syawla erew ereht tub
?ysae gnihtemos tuoba klat ew t'nod yhW"
.kcab enirevlow eht devohs ,ssenerawa on htiw dna
reccos gniyalp deppirt eh woh tuoba yrots a pu edam yehT
.hguoht drah adnik s'tI
,gniteerg llams a dias eH
.meht rof evom a ekam t'ndid eh ,niaga dna ,emas eht did ekalB .riahc sih morf gnidnats
.moor sih ot kcab flesmih desucxe ylkciuq eh
.elims ekalB edam taht esuom eht morf elkcuhc elttil suoived a saw erehT
.part a otni deppets tsuj d'eh ekil leef tub pleh t'ndluoc ekalB
.htaenrednu dekcut eit neerg gnihctam saw ralloc eht rednu tsuJ
elttil otni
.ti dedeen taht esoht dnefed ot dliub dna ezis sih gnisu syawla
.cilbup ni kcab claC PA ni saw I
.emoh og annaw tsuj I"
.mih dniheb gniwollof xof eht raeh t'ndid tub
.ekawa enirevlow eht koohs ekalB dna srood elbuod eht sdrawot deklaw kcirtapztiF .rD
.enirevlow eht revo eye na dah ohw
esoht taht wonk uoy diD"
gnitlover a no dah eh yadoT
.ytiucsimorp lauxeS .esuba gurD
.ekalB trofmoc ot gniyrt ,dias dranreB ",ruoh na eb ylno
.rehtegot gnimoc saw taht nalp eht rof
mih no kcab sih denrut yob rehto eht nehT
.laem nwo sih otni gniggid
.hctam ot eit a htiw tsev elygra wolley deroloc dessip
.mra sih rednu meht dekcut dna srepap eht pu dekcip netram enip eht ,ti pord ot tsuJ ".ees
.dne eht ta hgual evissimsid a gnidda ,dias eh
.daeh sih koohs dna tuo ruf nworb dna kcalb sih deltsirb
.deb sih no deppord yletaidemmi eh ,edisni tog eh nehw dna ti morf raf t'nsaw moor siH
.kcirtapztiF .rD ro lapicnirp eht ot klat nac ew ebyaM
,gnitirw saw eh seirots eht dnuof stnerap sih nehW
!thginot gnimoc rof enoyreve uoy knahT"
.gnihtyna yas t'ndid tub ,ecnalg sih deciton kcirtapztiF .rD
.dnoces a rof meht dleh dna edisni srepap eht devohs eH
.ereht tuo og uoy ,haN"
,tnangidni elttil a gnileef ,ekalB ".melborp
.egats ffo deklaw ehs sa reh ot kcab gnivaw saw enoyreve ekil tlef tI
.erow yllacipyt eh nirg tfos eht otni kcab deppils elims ediw sih esuaceb
.eye eht ni ekalB kool t'ndluoc eh tub ,mih sdrawot pu daeh sih denrut esuom ehT
.worbeye na gnisiar ,deksa ekalB "?keew tsaL"
,derettum eh ",ni emoC"
,ylprahs dias dranreB ",em evohs t'noD"
.sredluohs sih deggurhs dna hgual a fo hpmh a tuo tel eH .spil sih fo pag eht dnuora depparw eugnot a fo pit eht ,daetsnI
.dloc teg dluoc seldoon sih erofeb doof sih dehsinif oot eh
,muidop reh tsuj ot deniartser eb t'ndluoc rodarbal ehT
.hcnul rof pu dewohs reven eh nehw yrrow ot gninnigeb saw ekalB
.nalp ot emit hguone naht erom tog eW
.noil eht ot resolc elttil a pets dranreB dehctaw eh nehT
"?ereh fo tuo teg annog er'ew woh tuo derugif uoy evaH ?uoy tuoba tahW"
.mih htiw srepap eht ekat ot mih degru
,stnap nat ikahk desserp
.deggeb yllacitcarp eh
",rehto hcae tcerroc ot
.daeh sih gnikahs ,ni trons tew a koot dranreB
.yas dluow eh esle gnihtyna raeh ot gnitnaw yllaer ton
.ylkciuq htrof dna kcab daeh sih gnikahs ,netram enip eht morf kcab dellup eH
.llab yalp ot mih teg ot xof eht fo noisluver nepo sih gnisu saw eh ekiL
.won ni em tel yehT
.htiw nioj t'ndid netram enip eht taht hgual a tuo gnicrof ,dias eh
.etapicitrap ot mih ksa ot evah t'ndid kcirtapztiF .rD
,rof ereht ni saw eh tahw yltcaxe wenk tnedor eht ekil demees ti dna
,flehs eht no kcab erutcip eht decalp xof ehT
,ffo tnew rezzub a erofeb ruoh na tuoba rof taht did yehT
,uoy brutsid ot ylekil si ypareht noisrevnoc fo mrof eht ni esuba suoigiler ro ,lailimaf
",sdne doirep tsrif erofeb tsuj
.esruoc fo ,ti weiver ew litnU
srepap eht ni selpmid thgils erew erehT
.edanomel fo ssalg a morf pleh emos htiw nwod ti decrof eh os ,rennid erofeb teg annog saw eh lla saw tI
ees dluoc rotcod eht erofeb yawa gninrut
,egats eht fo tnorf ni seenk sih ot llef dna drawrof nar eH
,pu daeh sih denrut ekalB ".relluF .rM"
.seenk sih neewteb daeh sih htiw esuom eht saw deb sih no gnittiS
.dneirf sih rof elims a ecrof ot gniyrt ,dias eh
.ecnedifnoc emos htiw ti mrofrep ot woh mih gniwohs dna dnammoc eht gniziromem ,retnirp eht tuoba deksa eh nehw flesreh fo duorp demees ylno ehS
.dworc eht fo mhtyhr eht htiw evom ot flesmih ecrof ot dah eh dna htrof dna kcab deyaws smra siH
,sretupmoc eht gnisu s'tneduts eht lla no eye na tpek
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY  .emit rehtona
ylthgirb gnilims llits saw noil ehT
.taes sih morf pu doots xof eht dna ,dias eh
,saw ti erehw wenk eH
",worromot yad ilobmorts s'tI !tuo demmub eb t'naC"
a otni tog netram enip eht
"?buc a erew uoy nehw ot pu dekool uoy serugif ro srettisybab ynA
.elzzum dna eson sih morf doolb gniyrd eht ffo dehsaw yeht tub
.mih dniheb rood eht gnikcolnu ydaerla xof eht ,taes sih morf esor eH
mih gnitcessid saw eh ekil
.noisserpeD" "—reven ev'I"
.mlac dna dicalp gniniamer syawla
,ybraen saw xof eht fi ees ot ton ,dnuora detrad seye siH
.eloh lleh siht ni mih dneirfeb ot tsrif eht fo eno saw eH
.ecnetnes yreve neewteb-ni denroheohs snossel lacilbib htiw
.trap sih enod gnivah ,ffo deklaw noillats ehT
"?ailihpodep dna ytilauxesomoh
.ytilamrof eht eraps t'ndluoc I dna ni emoc stneduts wen nezod a tsael ta dah ev'I
.ylkciuq mih dniheb rood eht gnisolc ,deksa ekalB "?dranreB"
,daeh sih detfil esuom ehT
.seye nwo sih otni gnirob stils enipluv ,dias eh
.yltnetni meht gnihctaw
,tem yeht thgin tsrif taht deb sih morf nwod emac eh dna
.mih rof dediced ydaerla saw erutuf sih
.gniod m'I tahw s'taht os ,hcraeser nwo ym od ot em detnaw uoY .flesruoy ti dias uoY"
,ecnatsid eht esolc annog saw eh ekil dekool eH
.ta gnitteg saw xof eht tahw erus yllaer ton ,esor worb s'ekalB ".taht erimda I
.nees gnieb fo tnemssarrabme eht dneirf sih gniraps ,ylkciuq neercs eht ot kcab sucof sih nrut ot dah ekalB
.nwod tis neve dluoc xof eht erofeb gnikaeps ydaerla
.sdneirf sih dna thgin tsal htiw decnad I yug emos tsuJ"
.ni gninioj tuohtiw dleif eht fo dne eno no dnats tsuj dluoc eh esuaceb yltsom
.ti otni derats eh sa emarf eht fo srenroc eht ta debbur bmuht siH
"?em rof taht od uoy naC
ycnecalpmoc etaerc ot tuo dednah loohcs eht
;rehto hcae thgif ot su tnaw yehT
"?sdoow eht otni nur tsuj annaw uoY"
",elbuort ni teg ll'uoY"
.tuo delworg tsomla ekalB
.uoy sevol doG ,wonk tsuJ"
.enola eciffo s'kcirtapztiF .rD fo edistuo tas ekalB
dias taht ngis elttil a htiw ytpme
.reh rof palc ot nageb dnats t'ndid taht esohT
.erutuf ruoy rof tseb s'tahw tnaw tsuj eW
.yrasrevinna htnom tsrif ruoy fo yad eht no uoy fo lla ees ot tniop a ti ekam yllausu I .sey hO"
.mih htiw gnicnad saw
.eludehcs eht was dna ni kcab tnew I nehw eciwt kniht neve t'ndid yehT
.noitom eht ta elttil a pu gnineffits ,ooc llams a tuo tel dranreB
.htap s'doG morf yarts ot sevlesruo wolla tonnac eW
,erofeb ti enod reven d'eH
.pihw a htiw mih ta gnippans ekil ,hguoht noitnetta rof eugnot sih dekcilc xof ehT
.mih ot pu mraw ot tsekciuq eht fo eno neeb dah dranreB
.gnirob gnikcuf os si ymonoretueD ,huG" .lufreehc naht ssel saw noitcaer s'nilloC hguoht ,kcirt eht od ot demees tahT ".lufpleh
,cibohpreeuq gninrecnoc yrots a fI
.gnitirw sih gnippots tuohtiw deksa eh
,trohs saw smrod eht ot klaw ehT ".uoY
.tnorf eht ta gninepo eht ot gnivom lla
.noitasrevnoc a saw ti ekil tsomla ,yllausac snoitseuq deksa tsuJ
.elzzum s'kcirtapztiF rD no elims sselhtoot tfos a saw erehT ".uoy knahT"
,gniyas erofeb ylthgils daeh sih gniwob ,yob eht ot don a evag eH
,elzzum sih fo sedis eht nwod gninnur skcart raet dah eH
,deksa mih morf ssorca esuom eht
.lanoitnetni saw taht ebyam ekil leef tub pleh t'ndluoc eH
.mih etagorretni ot nageb ohw legnA naidrauG a yb deppots saw eh ,esirprus on oT
.delttesnu saw eh revenehw did eh kcit suovren a fo gnihtemos daetsni tub
.niaga esnet og dranreB leef dluoc eh dna deppots gnibbur ehT
,deksa esuom eht litnu rehtruf yna yawa gnillup ton ,deppots eH .detfil ydaerla mra
.hcnul ta mih htiw ti revo og ot detnaw I rehcaet eht dlot dna
.moor nwo sih ot kcab yaw sih depmots neht
,syaw retsinis ni skrow lived ehT
.gnitsalb cisum eht htiw neve debrutsidnu yletelpmoc ,gnillaf dna gnisir tsehc egral sih ees dluoc ekalB
.morf gnimoc saw dranreB erehw dnatsrednu dluoc ekalB
.sevitcele eht ni llif ot seiduts elbib tnereffid nezod a htiw gnola
.yldliw smra sih gnivom dna
.bal retupmoc eht dnif ot loohcs eht hguorht htap ydniw gnol a koot eh ,daetsnI
.erew ereh stneduts eht fo tsom hguoht ,ekalB ro dranreB ekil ,yag t'nsaw nilloC ".ereh
.drawnwod gnicnalg morf flesmih peek t'ndluoc eh ,kool ot tnaw t'ndid eh nehw nevE
.citsillab gnikcuf og ll'eh ,tuo sdnif eh fI"
.gnitsiwt morf elzzum sih peek ot thgif ot dah ekalB ".niaga
,mih denioj dah nilloC dna dranreB
,emoh uoy teg ot tnaw eW
,reduol tib a deklat airetefac eht ni enoyrevE
,llew sa thgim eh gnirugiF
suoedih a erow eH
.rehtegot tup gnihtemos dah eh taht erus saw eh litnu nalp eht fo nilloC llet t'ndid ekalB
.eerf saw eh nehw neve
,ni tpels yeht taht sdeb knub eht ekiL
,deksa kcirtapztiF .rD
.yldneirf oot ton ,dias ekalB
,detaeper neht dna nwo sih otni swap s'xof eht gnikat ,dias eh ",uoy knahT"
.dehcnelc ylbisiv taorht
",smoor ruo ot kcab og su tel yeht litnu tis tsuj rehtar d'I
.yliraew edisni gnikcud
.srae sih ni gnignir llits saw cisum kcoR naitsirhC eht raews dluoc ekalB dna
.redluohs sih revo mra na gnipparw ,ylkciuq ni devom ekalB
.mih ees ot emac eh yhw nosaer elohw eht ot gnitteg yllanif ,dias ekalB
.uoy ekil stneduts thgirb sdrawot ytiniffa na evah did syawla I ,wonk uoY"
",elyts ym ekil t'ndid yeht sseug I
,htiw railimaf oot gnimoceb saw eh eciov gnizinortap tfos taht draeh eh litnu dnim sih degnahc evah thgim dranreB taht thguoht eh ,tsrif tA
thgir mih evorP
.desolc seye dna dedlof smra
.ksed eht fo edis s'ekalB ot drawrof meht gnihsup
.si nis tahw s'tahT
.mih evael t'ndid hcuot s'kcirtapztiF .rD
.ti fo tsom gnissim s'eno siht dnA
.noitnetta yap ot gnivah ylerab mih ,yb demooz sessalc s'ekalB fo tser ehT
.hgis tnasaelp a htiw dias eh
"!evol eurt si evol siH"
.doom reireehc a ni eb ot demees elbat gnidnuorrus eht ni syob eht dna
.mhtyhr s'rehtona eno dehctam yeht sa teef gnihcuot ,sgel rieht detfil yehT
.kcen s'netram enip eht no daeh sih gnitser saw dna noops gib fo elor eht koot eh ,dnuora emit emit sihT .mih
.mih egnellahc ot ekalB gniwolla ton ,detpurretni eh
dda ot esle tahw wonk t'ndid eH
",uoy eltrats ot naem t'ndid I"
.dluoc eh sa yllacitamolpid sa dias eh
srekaeps eht no denepo kcoR naitsirhC
.eugnot sih no gnitiaw oN eriferus a dah eh ekil
.mih fo tnorf ni yltfos egami eht devaw dna denrut eh nehT
,ti raeh ot tnaw ton thgim uoY"
",erus rof ,ssenkaew a s'tI
.reehc thgirtuo ot nageb elpoep dna
,dekil eh gnos a fo ydolem eht demmuh eH
nac I !muirotidua siht ni s'tI
.tcatnoc-eye niatniam ot deniarts tub
,mih no nrow dah daerd ehT
,pihsrow saw thgin tA
.eciffo s'kcirtapztiF .rD fo edistuo
.emit tsrif eht rof sgnaf dna hteet gniwohs
.mih gnillet saw xof eht tahw dnatsrednu ot nageb eh dna seye s'kcirtapztiF .rD dniheb nwohs thgil thgirb A
.sessalc sih fo lla ni s'A thgiarts tog ekalB taht rettam t'ndid tI .2 fo 1 trap ,etoyoC triD yb ”nuR“
.meht fo
.enola siht od t'nac I tub ,enif eb ll'tI
eno ton si nwo yM .snoitan s’dlrow eht fo %11 ylno ni dewaltuo neeb sah
.sdrow reh sa hcum sa swap reh htiw os did ehs ,ekops rotsap eht nehW
.riahc nwo sih ot dnuora deklaw eh sa ksed sih fo tnorf ni taes a ot detniop eh nehT
.rehtegot ecnad dluoc yeht ecnatsid etairporppa eht meht gniwohs
,gnitirw siht fo emit tA
.taht ta daeh sih koohs ekalB
—" "—yllanosrep ereht uoy ekat ll'I dna
"?relluF .rM ,uoy ekil nem gnuoy ekil I yhw wonk uoY"
.reyarp ni pihsrow eht gnitrats
.emoh og ot tnaw I"
.nam redlo eht htiw mih evael ot detnaw eh fi erus yllaer ton
.tsaf ytterp seog ti dna ,raeh ot stnaw eh tahw mih llet —tsuJ"
"?ydaerla yb enog skeew owt sah ,yhW"
,keew eht fo tser ehT
.ylraelc noitcartta rieht ees dluoc ekalB dna
!ilobmorts ekil uoY"
teef sih pu gnikcik saw esuom ehT
semitemos esuaceb ,epacse tsuj s’ti semitemoS
.mih yarteb reven dluow yeht taht flesmih dlot eh taht rettam t'ndid ti
,noitatiseh yna evah t'ndid nilloC
.lamron emaceb gnihtaerb sih yllanif litnu noisnet tsol ylwols ydob s'dranreB
.eno draeh reve
,ecin tsuj osla saw tI .taht mih evag eh dna
,desolc eciffo s'kcirtapztiF .rD ot rood eht sa denetsil eH
,mih revo dehcnuh saw ekalB
,detcejretni eh erofeb dnoces a ylno rof dekcarc elzzum s'netram enip ehT "—
.rehtnaP emiT-lluF a ,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer
.hcnul rof emit saw ti enoyreve gnitrela
.s'esuom eht neewteb waptoof sih gnizeeuqs ,gel sih detfil eH
,seigolohtna gnimocpu
.buc xof llams a saw tI
,sdraug owt fo ezag eht rednu saw tneduts yrevE
,tsafkaerb gnirud yggorg elttil a saw eh ,ylgnittimdA
tser eht morf tsehtruf tas taht erutcip a deciton eH .snaicitilop eb ot demussa eh tahw dna srotsap htiw swap gnikahs mih fo serutcip tsuj saw flehs rehtonA
.daeh sih koohs dna erom elttil a mih dezeeuqs eh ,daetsnI
.hcnul gniwollof eht yad ilobmorts tcaf ni saw ti
,srepap eht was eh nehw tub
.snoitatpmet ynam dah oot I ,uoy ekiL"
,gniyas ,yltnatcepxe daeh sih deddon kcirtapztiF .rD ".ylisae
.hcum oot delaever eh ekil leef eh did retfa ylno dna ,dias eh
.niaga taht ekil yob rehtona dloh ot ecnahc eht rof gnihtyna edart t'ndluow eh tub
.degac su peek ot ereh er'yehT
.snoitseuq eromyna ksa t'ndid yksuh eht dna
koot tI .tibbar eht rof ton ylniatrec saw ti hguoht ,delims dna reh deknaht eH
.delbuort saw eh ,oN
.erofeb sa ffits sa etiuq leef t'ndid smra s'netram enip eht dna
.eltit dethgilhgih eht ta gnitniop ,meht hguorht deppilf neht dna dias eh
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb ”nuR“
,kcirtapztiF .rD ot kcab denrut eh nehT
.ti rof dessap revetahw ro llabtoof deyalp daetsni ekalB
.tellaw ym tegrof ot dedneterp I dna egnuol ytlucaf eht ni eta eW
.fles regnuoy ym fo em dnimer uoY"
.uoy fo edisni s'tI
.sesion erom yna gnikam morf mih gnipeek ,elzzum s'esuom eht ot wap a dloh ot dah eH
.pu swap rieht dleh yeht yaw eht gnikcimim deirt eh ,tsrif tA
.evohs lufyalp llams a mih evag ,nilloC ,edis s'esuom eht yb enirevlow A ".seod enoyrevE
,gnidda erofeb nep sih fo pot eht gnikcilc ,dias eh ",roivaheb
,degnahc reven enot siH
.thgit ytterp dleif eht tpek secnef hgih toof neetfif ehT
.melborp ruoy reven saw tahT
,osrot sih revo gnignah saw daeh siH
.ereht pu og annog m'I"
.dedeen eh noitamrofni eht teg dluoc dranreB erofeb syad eerht
,gnicnad deppots syob htoB
.hcterts eht esu dluoc eh dna
—gniliec eht sdrawot seye sih dekcilf dna ria eht ni pu regnif a detniop eh—
,ti tuoba kniht ot emit deen dluow dranreB wenk eH
,tniop sih ot teg ot mih ksa yllacitsacras ot detnaw eH
.kciuq saw noisses eht fo tser ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,eye sih rof od dluoc yeht hcum t'nsaw erehT
.tsrif ti hctac ot eno eht eb yllausu dluow eh neht ,raf
.moor eht fo tuo deklaw neht dna don elgnis a evag ekalB
.eganam dluoc eh repsihw tsetfos eht ot eciov sih gnipeek ,denepo eh
.doohdlihc ruoy revo og s'teL
.esaelP .uoy ees ot doog os s'tI"
.esnopser etaidemmi na rof hsup t'ndid ekalB ,niaga
",meht ecnerefer-ssorc ot gnihton evah I dna dlo er'yehT .seiduts ruoY"
.kcab sih no ti gnitser ,nilloC ot revo wap suoituac a dehcaer dranreB
,detcepxe eh naht retteb saw doof ehT
",ekil I cisum eht neve ton s'tI .yllaer ton ,oN"
",syawyna liaf ot nalp tsuj I
.drow a gniyas tuohtiw edisni gniklaw ,esor ekalB
.ti tuoba deksa yob
.dnim sih otni denrub ecaf s'xof eht ni gnittips ekalB fo egami nA ".uoy sevol doG
kcab rewol sih no tap llams a tlef eh ,mih tsap deklaw eh sa tub
,ffo flesmih dellup ylluferac eh nehT
.drawrof devom kcab eht ni stneduts eht fo emoS
.ecno dnuora meht gnippalf ,keew eht ni reilrae dednah saw eh taht srepap eht pu dleh ekalB
.tuo dekcehc ydaerla dah enirevlow eht taht dezilaer eh tub ,nioj annog saw nilloC fi ees ot daeh sih denrut eH
,dias dna riahc nwo sih otni flesmih dexaler
.won ,oga htnom a naht erom neeb d'taht eveileb ot drah saw tI
.smra sih edisni yob rehto eht gnildarc
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
.mih ta pu dekool eh dna
.daeh sih deddon dna taorht sih ni plug a dih eh ,daetsnI
.tsol tsuj saw eh taht denialpxe dna eson sih rednu pils eht dleh netram enip ehT
.ylisae sdneirf ekam I .sseug I ,haeY"
.ni gnittif er'uoy erus ekam ot tsuj noisses etavirp llams A
",recnad a fo hcum ton m'I"
,ylluferaC .ecnedive
.relluF .rM ,sgniht
.yob rehto eht tsniaga kcab flesmih gnidils ,sredluohs sih dexaler ekalB
.ylkciuq dessih dranreB "!oN"
.relluF .rM ,rebmemeR"
.htaerb hcae htiw nwod dna pu gnivom ydob s'esuom eht fo noitasnes eht dehsiler eh dna ,ecin saw
.mra sih tsniaga eson sih depiw dna ,gnibbos fo elddim eht ni llits saw eH
,tsrif egats eht ot nettog d'ohw eno eht ,yob noil ehT
",tneduts a fo ledom elor tcefrep A
llird erif a s'ereht ,htxis eht nO"
enohp eht revo stnerap sih htiw klat ot ni dellac neeb ev'thgim eh taht enirevlow eht derussa eh tub ,ti tuoba deksa nilloC
.ledom elor tcefreP
.moor gnitiaw knalb eht naht tnereffid hcum saw eciffo ehT
.decaf yeht slairt eht dna elpoep laer fo seirots derahs ehS
.niaga uoy ees I nehw ,skeew owt ni ti tuoba klat ll'eW
.sdrow sih ni ssenrettib eht gnidih ton ,dias eh
.dnuora denrut eh litnu neeb dah ti gniniard yllanoitome woh dezilaer t'ndah eH
.tuhs kcol eht dekcilc dna ,mih dniheb rood eht desolc tsuj eH
.hguoht tnatropmi saw tI
"?uoy stius ti fi ees dna ereht tuo og uoy t'nod yhW ?roivaheb ruoy gnivorpmi tuoba dias ew tahw rebmemeR .nom'C"
.repap fo teehs a otni sgniht gnilbbircs nageb xof eht sa dehctaw ekalB ".ereht
ot teg t'ndid I yrros os m'I"
.seit etihw psirc dna
naicinhcet bal tibbar ehT
.nilloC ta regnif a detniop dna deddon ekalB
.taht stbuod eno oN
,airetefac wen sih ni gnittis saw eh ,daetsnI
sdrow s'xof eht revo thguoht eh sa koohs wap s'ekalB
,elkcuhc llams a gnivig ,dias eh
.tcejbus eht egnahc ot nrut s'netram enip eht saw tI
,rehtegot moor a derahs yehT
.sgnileef esoht ot ni evig tonnac ew tuB"
.lufpleh eb ll'taht ,em rof seton ekat dluoc owt uoy fi os ,yduts elbiB gnirud eb ll'tI .haey ,syawynA"
.htrof dna kcab mra s'esuom eht gnikahs ,dias ekalB ",pu ekaw ,yeH"
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta dna
yna ta kool ot gnilliw neve t'nsaw eh taht
,hguoht gnicnad tsuj saw tI
.ecnartne eht fo tnorf ni gnidnats
.raeh ot detnaw eh tahw rotcod eht gnillet tuoba sdrow s'dranreB derebmemer eH
,llah eht otni tuo saw eh sa noos sA
,seye sih gnillor ,deddon dranreB
,hcum ekil mees t'ndid tI
,taes sih ta llits saw kcirtapztiF .rD
.elytsefil tnedaced yrev a s'ti tub
.sdrawretfa sruoh wef a emitemos nwod gnibmilc
—" "—taht seod tahW ?tahW"
".ssalc ni ti dehsinif I .krowemoh arbegla ym hguorht og ot eerf leeF"
,og tel eh nehT ".uoy sevol doG"
.moorhtab gnikcuf eht ni em depmuj selohssa emoS"
,redluohs sih no wap a detser xof ehT ".rotcoD"
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dna ,edirP yppaH
,taes eht koot ylregae ekalB
.ereh zeuqsaV .rM srehtob eno on erus ekam ll'I
.don kciuq a evag ekalB
.mih nees reve dah ekalB naht reduol ,gnihgual saw eH
.ylsuounitnoc no gninord enihcam esion etihw eht fo dnuos eht htiw dellif ylno ria eht ,owt eht neewteb ecnelis s'tnemom a saw erehT
.mih tsuahxe ot detnaw eh esuaceb ,doog saw hcihW
,eciffo sih ot rood eht no dekconk eh nehw ,hguone eruS
.dnopser t'ndid tub ,deddon dranreB ".nalp
.loohcs eht fo muirotidua niam eht ni yadirF yreve detsoh yeht gnihtemos
.trihs seveels gnol etihw a revo tsev elygra neerg thgil
.nosaer a rof ymedacA htaP gnidiuG dellac s'tI
.meht dniheb tog dna gnidnats syob fo puorg eht ot denrut ekalB
"?dnim ruoy no gnihtemoS"
.cisum eht revo deksa eh
.daeh sih koohs dranreB ,niagA ".kcirtapztiF
"?pu s'tahW .yddub ,hcnul dessim uoY"
.tib tsethgils eht neve hctiwt spil sih tel t'ndluoc eH
.elbisnopser neeb ev'thgim ohw tuo gnikcip saw eh ekil
,deksa eh ,dnopser t'ndid ekalB nehW .stib
!em fo edisni s'tI
,rehtegot gnicnad syob erew erehT
"?nur ot yrt uoy diD
.relluF .rM ,swalf evah lla ew tub
.srenetsil emos ot gnibrutsid eb yam taht lairetam sniatnoc edosipe gniwollof ehT
.syoB rof ymedacA htaP gnidiuG ot tnes saw ekalB
eniuneg yletelpmoc saw ,revewoh erow eh elims ehT
.steehs eht rednu deirc eh sa
.yalp ot nageb cisum sa reh dniheb llef neercs rotcejorp A
,dehsinif saw eh nehW
.deb eht fo edis eht no mih gninoops ,nwod flesmih thguorb eh ,nehT
secruoser emos pu kool I t'nod yhW
ruoy ni stnemevorpmi nwohs ev'uoy ecno
.uoy htiw tuo gnignah eciohc thgir eht edam I" .detrons nilloC
.hgual llams a tuo tel ekalB ".eludehcs
,riahc sih ni kcab gninael saw enipluv eht ,ruoh flah a retfA
.ti gniod erew sneet rehto eht lla nehw neve ,deew fo tih a ro
,lleW .gnihton ,haN"
.noitom llams a ni daeh sih koohs ekalB "?thguac teg
,eugnot nwo sih otni knus hteeT ".uoy
",esimorp I ,siht fo tuo teg ll'eW"
.evaw trohs a gnivig ,dias eh
.egnuol ytlucaf eht ni ti was I"
nwod smra sih werht netram enip ehT
.ereh fo tuo su teg ot nalp a evah I kniht I .netsiL"
.elbatrofmocnu demees yob rehtien tub
.rehtruf yna ti sserp ot ton dootsrednu dna ,ot dedneterp tsuj eh ro ,tahT
tuo ti werht rotcurtsni eht fi dna syob eht fo tsom naht retsaf saw netram enip ehT
.hhS" .rae sih ni hsuhs ot dah netram enip eht dna ,ekalB rof duol oot elttil a saw eciov siH
,stifeneB htiw sruF desaeler yltnecer eht ni skrow sih dnif nac uoY
,ti rebmemer ot od dluoc eh lla saw tI
elzzum sih no elims yrw llams a saw erehT
,airetefac eht dnuora ezag ot demees seye s'nilloC
!laer s'tI !eurt s'tI"
.nam gnuoy doog a s'tahT"
tsom ruo stceffa ti woh ees nac uoy dnA
.mih htiw cisum sih fo yna gnirb ot dewolla gnieb ton
".erehwon fo elddim eht ni si ecalp sihT
.egats niam eht morf wor tsehtruf eht ni ,kcab eht ni tas ekalB
.krof sih htiw dnuora faoltaem devohs eh sa taht tuoba gnikniht ,hgis a tuo tel ekalB
.flehs eht no serutcip fo wor eht sdrawot yllufthguoht gniklaw ,taes sih fo tuo tog xof ehT
.ni emac dranreB nehw raeh neve t'ndid eH
,sessalc retfa bal retupmoc eht ni yad a ruoh nA .hcraeser ruoy od nac uoY"
.tiaw uoy elihw mih ot yarP .uoY sevoL doG
.raeh ot tuoba era uoy yrots eht yb detaler sa stneve eht tuoba ytiugibma on eb ereht teL
.noitcepsni gninrom eht gnirud thguac gnitteg gniksir ekalB ,did yehT
!evol eurt si evol siH
?tnaw dluow eh tahw taht si
.relluF .rM ,nam gnuoy thgirb a er'uoY
,redluohs sih morf gnisaeler wap eht ,pu tog eH
.seye sih fo sedis eht ta gnillew ydaerla sraet ,dias eh
.daeh sih fo pot eht ffo elpoep cificeps yna fo kniht dluoc eh taht ton ,seman yna mih evig t'ndid ekalB
.tuo gnimoc noil a rof yaw eht fo tuo deppets eH
.gnir dluow lleb txen eht erofeb hcnul rieht dehsinif dna
.stneduts fo ydob regral eht htiw
.yawa skeew owt tsomla si htxis ehT
.rehtnap emiT-lluF a ,ybigreK yb daeR
.pu derats yob rehto eht sa nwod gnirats
,si taht tahw wonk uoy kniht I"
.rennid ta ti tuoba snoitseuq fo tol a dah nilloC dna
,dneirf sih morf yawa ezag sih detreva ylwols ekalB
"?regnol elttil a
.gnissim saw dranreB
,evael ot meht rof yletilop tuo dleh mra sih htiW
dna ecnelis saw ereht niagA .derepsihw eh
em gnillet speek eH
tsuj…siht od ew naC"
,meht htiw htrof dna kcab deyaws eH
.nellows saw pil sih ees dluoc eh dna
,ylwols peels sih morf derrits dranreB
.tup deyats yletamitlu tub ,sredluohs sih delggirw eH
.nur ot mih dewolla ti esuaceb tsom eht taht dekil eH
taht ta dehgual puorg ehT
.seye sih ta gnipiw llits ,moor gnitiaw eht fo tuo deklaw eh sa ecnalg a ekalB gniraps neve ton noil eht
,nevig neeb d'eh seiduts eht tuoba gniklat ekil leef t'ndid ekalB
.gnittis saw eh erehw sdrawot kcab demrots dna
,dias eh dna redluohs s'yob eht no dednal wap siH
"?thgirla ni gnittif uoy erA
.elif eht ni taht yas dluohS
.yltfos mih gnilddarts
.naeco na ni sevaw ekil gnivom smra rieht
.seno doog eht fo eno eb d'uoy wenk I"
.riahc sih no ylbatrofmocnu delffuhs eh dna dekcarc ronaemed s'ekalB
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,ybraen saw eh ekil demees syawla tI
.od ot hcraeser nwo ym evah I ebyam ekil smees tI"
.rood eht fo edis rehto eht morf
,dias dna yawrood sih tsniaga denael kcirtapztiF .rD
,lufhtuom a htiw dias eh sa wollaws ot gnirehtob ton dna elzzum sih gnillif ,daoltaem sih fo egdew gib a koot ekalB
.rats kcor a saw ehs ekil tuo gnihcaer swap rieht htiw syob os ro ytnewt ,won egats
.mih rof nepo ti gnidloh erofeb ti gnikcolnu ,rood eht ot tsrif saw kcirtapztiF .rD
.secalp elpuoc a s'erehT"
,dedda kcirtapztiF .rD ,tfel eh sA
",won ereht em ekat nehT
.nam redlo eht ot kcab gninrut erofeb seye sih depiw eh dna
.pu dnats yob a dehctaw ekalB dna
",tuo demmub elttil a tsuJ .yllautca ,gnihtyreve ekil erom
.ot pu kool dluoc nem gnuoy rehto eht enoemoS .uoy ekil hcum yrev saw eH"
.sdneirf sih htiw tae ot gnirreferp ,esuom eht rof detiaw ekalB
.gnihtyreve xif dluow taht fi sa
.ytlucaf eht htiw hcnul gnivah saw ro
.tsehc sih sdrawot dekcud elzzum sih htiw yawa deklaw dna
,don a evag ylno eH
,hguoht flesmih esopmoc ot kciuq saw eH
.elims yls a pu decrof eh neht dna ,desuap eH ".gniod
.mih ot txen gnittis kcirtapztiF .rD gniees
.tcatnoc eye ekam ot ton gniyrt ,deggurhs netram enip ehT
.gnis ot nageb neercs no dnab a elihw stneduts eht ot devaw ehS
"?hcnul ta gniod erew uoy tahw taht sI"
,elzzum gnol s'enipluv eht ssorca daerps elims A ".emoh
?taht wonk uoy dluow woH"
,dias dna ni denael ,dah eh naht eromyna noitasrevnoc eht romuh ot gnitnaw ton ,ekalB ".erutuf
.gnillews eht htiw pleh ot
.gniod saw eh tahw wonk t'ndid eh ekil snoitseuq htiw reh gniborp ,reh detset ekalB
.don kciuq a evag dna dehgis eH
.tcelfer ot stneduts eht rof semitemos dna hgual ot stneduts eht rof semitemos
.mih sdrawot srepap eht dehsup dna
.yletaidemmi mrod sih ot kcab nruter t'ndid ekalB
.hcamots sih otni nwod lla ti plug mih
,seiduts eht otno gnidloh llits
,derepsihw esuom eht
,redlof eht morf srepap fo kcats a tuo dellup xof ehT ".taht
",—selohssa emoS .oN"
"—ew dna nilloC llet ll'I .thgirlA"
",seno doog eht fo eno m'I ,yldesoppuS
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.gniht a yas t'ndid ;mih tpurretni t'ndid eH
.ereht er'ew erofeb og ot syaw elttil a tog ew kniht I ,ylknarf dnA"
.tuo detnaw ohw esoht dna
.tfihs mih ot txen taes eht tlef eH
.emit a ta swalc owt htiw draobyek eht ta yawa gnicat-cit
,lufrednow gniod era uoy ,oN
rehtien dna ksed sih fo edis eno ot meht devohs ylkciuq eh os
.mih rof rehtruf rood eht denepo dna wap a tuo dleh eH ".esaelP
.srood eht dnuora gnuh yllausu taht slegnA naidrauG eht fo eno saw tI
.hturt eht fo diarfa gnieb tuoba
ylprahs redlof allinam a nepo deppilf eH ".dluow
,deeps rieht rof hguone tsaf mees t'ndid cisum eht hguoht nevE
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
t'now eW" ,deksa dranreB ,hgis gnol a htiw ,yllaniF
,detegdif esuom eht ,taht tA ".ereh
.dneirf sih revo kool ot daeh sih denrut tub
.rotcod eht htiw gniyats naht retteb sdlrow ekil tlef ti ,llitS
,mih otni kcab dehsup dranreB
.niatrec rof gniht eno wenk eh ,dnim sih ni tuB
,deb s'ekalB otni kcuns esuom eht ,thgin tahT
dna mih sdrawot rehtruf seiduts eht dehsup xof eht
.wodniw ssalg denehtgnerts a fo tsom gnirevoc sniatruc eulb htiw mih dednuorrus sllaw etihW
.perp egelloc neve ro sesruoc tnemecalp decnavda on dah htaP gnidiuG ehT .eurt saw tI ".detnuts
ot nageb esiwrehto tub ,hcuot eht morf dehcnilf enirevlow ehT
.nworf a otni detfihs elzzum s'noil eht ylkciuq woh was ekalB
.ti teg nac ew sa dna erehw ,evol ekil
.ytinutroppo eht koot ecno reven eH
",esaelp ,mih llet t'nac uoY
,emoh og nac uoy taht raelc yltnadnuba ti edam stnerap ruoY"
,yrotciv ekat ot woh wonk ohw su fo esoht era ereht tub ,yrotciv etelpmoc a ton spahreP
.thgin doog a dneirf sih gnihsiw erofeb dias eh
.dluow uoy wenk I .dooG .dooG"
.ti ta kool ot ton deirt ylevitcnitsni eh nehw neve
.dennuts gnimees dranreB
,gniklat deppots kcirtapztiF .rD
kcats eht fo pot eht no ti gnicalp erofeb pils a no gnilbbircs ,reward a nepo dellup eH .ksed
htrof dna kcab ylwols mih dekorts tsehc sih dnuora swap ehT ".ereh fo tuo teg ew nehw stnega terces doog ekam ll'eW"
",egnellahc eht rof s'ti erus m'I"
,hguoht pag elbisiv a saw erehT
.htuoy elbarenluv
.thgin eht otni peed pu mih gnikaw
.thgiarts sredluohs ruoy peek ot woh no sessalc ro strops detaler enilucsam yltsom saw tI
.syadkeew eht naht tnereffid hcum t'nerew sdnekeew ehT
,dias dna redluohs s'ekalB degdun dranreB
.mrofinu ot gnidrocca desserp syawla era sehtolC .emit no edam syawla sdeB"
.knub eht pu debmilc dah netram enip eht dezilaer eh sa kaeuqs a tuo tel neht dna
.rewsna ot diarfa er'uoy yhw s'taht dna
,meht ot derrefer loohcs eht sa slegnA naidrauG ro
.ereh dnuora gnihtyna su llet t'nod yehT
,yawa meht werht eh fI
sdrawer llams eht saw siht
.flesruoy ot gnihtyna peek ot uoy tcepxe I tub
".relluF .rM ,em evol ot evah t'nod uoY"
.krowemoh htam sih hguorht gnikcip llits
,dias dna kcab deddon ekalB ".neht
,hguoht doof sih dehsinif eh sa noos sA
,yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.nwod demlac esuom eht litnu detiaw dna spil sih ot regnif a tup tsuj ekalB
.srepap eht ot kcab denrut eh sa sredluohs sih deggurhs dna
dna htaerb a koot eh sa depmuls dna esor sredluohs s'kcirtapztiF .rD
.regnol tib a rof ecarbme eht deyojne tsuj dna
tuoba klat ot skeew owt yreve rotcod eht ees ot deriuqer erew loohcs eht ta syob llA .xaler
I fi eil a s'taht woN"
.nilloC revo kool ot drawrof gninael ,deksa eh
",deb ot daeh dluohs su fo htob kniht I ,haeY"
.drawnwod reep t'ndid eh hguoht sgniht ffo gnidaer ,mih fo tnorf ni srepap eht ta deppat eH
.ti dehcaorppa dna nib hsart tseraen eht dnuof eh
",oot loohcs dlo ym ta sdneirf fo tol a dah I"
.elbuort oN .tnegilletni oS
.mih rof rewsna eht ni dellif eh ,dnopser t'ndid ekalB nehW .suoiruc dekcoc worbeye
,nialp saw moor gnitiaw ehT
flesmih nihtiw morf pu gnisir regna tlef ekalB ".moorhtab
.s'kcirtapztiF .rD tnereffid yrev eht naht
.yaw eht ni tog nam redlo na erofeb tsuj
.trohs sa tsuj erew srewsna rieht dna
",os kniht uoy dalg m'I"
.pu naelc mih depleh ekalB ,metsys sih fo tuo lla ti tog dah dranreB nehW
.srepap eht rof evom a ekam t'ndid dna ,smra sih dessorc ekalB ".nwo
.uoY sevoL doG :rebmemer dnA"
.ees uoy tahw fo esnes ekam ot elba eb ll'uoy taht wonk I dna
.edisa deppets dna
.smelborp yna evah t'ndid I"
dias ehs ",ti leef
,retal elttil a ni peels ot dewolla erew yehT
.hcraeser sih htiw flesmih ysub ot deunitnoc ekalB
.elpoep thgir eht rof pu gnikcits sthgif ynam oot ni toG
.dekrep srae detniop
.loohcs eht ni yltcerid ton fi esolc gnivil ylbaborp
.sthguoht nwo sih ni sdrow reh tuo nword ot tseb sih did ekalB dna ,desiar srieht tpek mih dna nilloC
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.stils enipluv prahs esoht hguorht mih gnihctaw
eniuneg erom tlef taht gnihtemos ,elims egral a erow ehS
.htiw railimaf ton m'I ecruos a morf eceip noinipo na tsuj si eno sihT"
,tiaw t'ndid ehS .ton did ekalB
.eye sih dnuora elcric krad a saw erehT
:esle lla evoba gniht eno rebmemer dnA !lla uoy knahT
,trap tsom eht rof seiduts eht revo tnew yehT
.dessertsid ylsuoivbo ,dias dranreB
.mih dnuora smra sih depparw dna
enihcam esion etihw a fo muh tfos eht saw erehT
”ypareht noisrevnoc“ flesti sllac hcihw esuba fo dnik eht
.detlah erew yas ot detnaw eh sdrow yna dna
,edisni ydaerla erew nilloC dna dranreB
,pihsrow s'yadirF tA
.taorht sih ni gniworg lworg eht edih ot elbanu ,deksa eh "?ti saw ohW"
.esolc mih gnidloh ,kcab sih ta dekorts ekalB ".emoh