,llirhs a emoceb won dah snoitarebrever ehT
.emit siht lla ereh neeb evah ot demees evila gnihton yhw ot sa tnih yeht did roN
.deneppah gnihton tub ,lenap eht deppat ehS
,wolg ot deunitnoc dnah reh no enur ehT
.sniur eht fo tser eht tuohguorht tnelaverp taht naht
.tnamrod deniamer latem eht no sngised ehT
,teef reh ta ,nehT
,dewolg yltfos senur eht ,desopxe ruf reh tfel stnemrag ecracs erehW
,ylesnetni erom snoitarebrever eht tlef ehs
,srehcraeser ssenredliw fo noitareneg reh ot euqinu saw lliks sihT
.ecalp siht tuoba ssenitpme railucep a saw erehT
.tserof eht pu gnithgil detroper neeb dah swolg egnarts ynam nehw
daD regdaB yldduC
.retal dnoces a gnidaf erofeb efil ot derekcilf snrettap erom
.tnaem siht fo lla tahw tuo erugif ton dluoc ehs neve tub
.deraen ehs sa evitaroced gnihtemos naht turts troppus a ekil erom dekool hcihw
.weiv morf gnidaf erofeb snrettap delgna ,digir ni drawtuo gnidaerps
.sgnihcte eht gnola sregnif reh dehsurb dna dnah a detfil elpaM   .nrettap A
,gnihsalf feirb a morf edisa tub
,esion elbidua ylerab fo enord tsethgils eht thguac gniraeh evitisnes s’elpaM
.ria gnidnuorrus eht tuohguorht snoitanoser feirb gnileef
.thgil eht detcelfer sniur eht ni ffo raf gnihtemos ,gninthgil fo hsalf yreve htiW
.drawno deunitnoc dna niaga ecno reh dnuora thgit kaolc reh dellup ehs ,ruopnwod eht ta tuo gnikooL
.llaf ot nugeb yllaudarg dah niaR
.sniur eht tsdima secruos thgil rehto on was ehs taht ,revewoh ,egnartS
,stnecs railimaf yna hctac ot deirt dna eson reh detfil reed ehT
.sgnidnuorrus reh otni ,fles fo ecnesse reh ,ecneserp reh delennahc yldrawtuo yeht sa meht tlef ehS
,ydob rednels a dna gnihtolc laminim htiw nevE
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.niaga gniraeppasid erofeb senots eht ssorca dnah reh morf drawtuo derekcilf senil tniaf ,dewolg senur reh sA
.ekauq llams a ekil ydob reh pu dna sevooh reh hguorht gnitanoser
.yrellag sih ni krowtra dna seirots htob htiw
.reh rednih ton did ti tub
.latem eht otni dehcte snrettap tniaf deciton ehS
.snmuloc enots suoremun rof evas ,tnacav saw aera txen ehT
.trapa gnillaf eb yam ecalp siht taht thguoht eht ta deredduhs elpaM
.etagitsevni ot tnemele eno tub saw gniwolg suoiretsyM
.reh dniheb deraeppasid dah efil fi sa saw tI
.ruf nworb-yddur reh tsniaga leef ot elpaM rof hguone
,sraey fo sdnasuoht retfa ereh llits erew sniur ehT
,suileA yb ”revaeW enuR“
.pih reh ta lehctas eht dehctulc dna
.noitartsurf ni detrons elpaM
,drawtuo daerps ecneserp reh sa pu til
.dnuora decnalg reed ehT
.senots ybraen eht no weiv otni derekcilf snrettap ekil-tiucric sa woleb snoitarebrever eroM   .delbmur rednuhT
.sevooh reh rednu snoitarbiv thgils yb deinapmocca gnieb ti deciton ehs ,revewoh ,emit sihT
.evitcani dna knalb deniamer neercs eht tub
?noitaunitnoc a yeht ereW
.snrecnoc ytefas rof rehtruf detagitsevni dah ydobon hguoht
.niar esned eht hguorht ecap reh pu deppets elpaM
,niar eht ni yawa dehsaw ton dah llits senur reh mrifnoc ot ydob reh ta nwod decnalg ylkciuq ehS
,efas demeed saera ot resolc dna resolc gniraeppa neeb dah swolg eht demialc smaet tuocs tneceR
.dniheb gnihton tfel dna gnihtyreve deruoved dah noisorroc fi sa
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
,dum dna tsud ylno emoceb dah sniur s’etis eht was ehS
,secnaraeppasid tsrif eht ecnis sraey ,won dnA
.tnereffid ylthgils saw nrettap ehT
?smaet tuocs tsal eht fo tahw tub
,erofeb deretnuocne dah ehs yrtiucric fo epyt emas eht eb ot demees yeht ,ecnalg tsrif tA
.noitcetorp dereffo osla reh no detniap snrettap etacirtni ehT
,tey tsuj tuo erugif ton dluoc elpaM tahw fo hguoht
,ffuc tsirw reh ta nwod dekool ehS
tserof eht hguorht deklaw erugif enol a sa yks eht deduorhs yponac yfael ,kciht A
.ecnatsid eht ni sremmilg deton seye neek reH
.trapa gnimoc eb ot demees yrtiucric lanretni s’etis eht neve ,tnew ehs rehtruf ehT
,ekil-reed ,dionamuh—
.yawa yleritne despalloc dah reh erofeb roolf ehT
.teef reh ta krowenots eht fo skcarc eht ni gniworg sdeew dna sessarg ees ot detcepxe ehS
.sniur eht tuohguorht gniohce
,dewollof rednuht sa dna ,evoba dehsalf gninthgiL
.elcatceps eht fo thgis eht ta dekcilf srae s’elpaM
.etis eht dehcaer reve dah teem ot saw ehs maet noitidepxe eht taht ngis yna ron thgil fo ecnedive rehtien saw ereht
,rehtruf reh denokceb srewsna fo ytilibissop ehT
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR .tenalPruF yb
,pecib reh no retsloh eht morf dapatad llams a dellup ehS
.neeb ecno dah snmuloc dna sllaw erehw tas elbbur fo sdnuoM
,niaga delbmur rednuhT
.tnemnorivne eht htiw ygolonhcet suoiretsym sti desuf dah dlroW dlO eht taht seiroeht dehctam esehT
ydob reh gnola senur ehT
,oga shtnom wef a litnu noitarolpxe rehtruf ot stimil-ffo demeed neeb ecnis dah aera ehT
,dapatad reh deretslohnu elpaM
.gninthgil fo sehsalf yb detpurretni ssecorp a ,denekrad yks eht sa drawno deunitnoc elpaM
.ecnalab ffo reh gniworht ,kcen reh ffo kaolc dehcnerd reh deknay ylraen tsug neddus A .derettum ehs
.gnahrevo ykcor a rednu htaerb reh hctac ot desuap dna serutcurts enots eht dehcaer yllanif ehS
.dehcaorppa elpaM
,yletamitni ,leef ot reh ekil srehto gniwolla
?noitcennoc eht saw tahW   .doots ehs erehw
,daehrevo sevael kciht eht dehcaerb spord fo rettulf thgils A
.ydaets eb ot deraeppa snmuloc dna sllaw eht ,dnuora dekool ehs sa hguoht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.noos gninioj eb dluow ehs maet noitidepxe eht fo stnih yna tceted ot yreneerg esned hguorht dereep seye lufepoh ,thgirB
,rehpargotpyrc fo noitanibmoc a
,reh dnuora lla sdnuos gnilbmurc ekil demees tahw ta dennap dna dekcilf srae reh ,deklaw ehs sA
.ecalp siht tuoba laiceps os saw tahw tuo erugif yllufepoh ot slicnuoc hcraeser eht yb nopu dellac neeb dah slliks euqinu reH
,pmac pu gnittes snoinapmoc reh fo esoht yllufepoh
.no og ot erom dedeen elpaM .sisehtopyh rehtona niaga tey saw siht tuB
.lamina ro tnalp rehtehw
.yletelpmoc gniraeppasid dna tuo gnirekcilf erofeb
.tip evissam a dleheb dna egdel nekorb eht dehcaorppa ylluferac elpaM
.denediw seye reh sa dekcilf srae reH
.rednuht fo elbmur rehtona ,hsalf gninthgil rehtonA
.ecalp siht etagitsevni ot denommus neeb dah ehs yhw saw hcihw ,smrots fo ecneserp eht ni swolg denialpxenu denoitnem stroper gnituocs ehT
.seert erab ,rellat laever ot gniraelc a otni denepo htap ehT
.no gniyrruh dna niaga ti gniwots erofeb
.dlroW dlO eht fo egdelwonk nettogrof-gnol eht yb dehcuot neeb dah noiger siht ,yldetbuodnU
,detemmulp reed eht dna
erutcurts ekil-gnir ,suomrone na ot detcennoc ti deciton dna dewollof dah ehs turts troppus eht ot pu decnalg ehS
.llaw enots eht no kcab dnah reh decalp dna tuo dehcaer ehS
.sremmilg eht raen ezah s’niar eht ni thgil tniaf deciton neht ehS
.ydaerla reh nopu saw mrots ehT
.sucof ot seye reh desolc dna tuo dehtaerb ehS
.ssenredliw desuF sti ni gnieb gnivil yreve hguorht ,seirots
,epacsdnal eht pu til ylfeirb gninthgiL
meht dnuora dlrow eht
,emit emos etiuq ni ereh neeb dah efil fo tros yna taht ecnedive on was ehs ruopnwod yvaeh eht ni neve tuB
.yletelpmoc tuo gniog erofeb derekcilf margoloh eht tub
.ecafrus euqapo-esiwrehto eht htaeneb morf gniwolg erew yeht fi sa tsomla gniraeppa
,daeh reh detlit elpaM
.stiucric ekil depahs eb ot deraeppa ,tcaf ni ,yeht dezilaer ehs ,snrettap eht tuo dehcteks elpaM sA   .esle elttil dna
.tnew ehs rehtruf eht raor a ot elbmurg a morf gnitfihs ,won meht draeh neve ehS
.stnemele s’erutan tsniaga trofmoc hguone dedivorp ruf reh
.ecneserp reh dednetxe ehs sa niaga ecno pu til senur reH
,niar eht ni denruhc egduls sa seslup neerg-wolley ,tneloiv ni dewolg retnec peed s’tip ehT
.reh fo tnorf ni thgis eht ni koot ehs sa dedlof srae reh dna ,denediw seye reH
.ria eht ni snoitarebrever s’mrots eht yb detpursid
,roloc dedaf fo hsalf a thguac ehs netfo os yrevE .sselerutaef dna dekcarc saw ti fo hcum oS
,pu til gnihton hguohT
enots otni denil yrtiucric dlo-ega dnoyeb gnihton dedleiy stpmetta noitavacxe devorppa wef yrev eht sa ,revewoh ,tseb ta yhcteks saw ecnedivE
.sllaw eht raen sgnahrevo eht ot esolc gnipeek ,drawno dettort elpaM   .gniwolG
.ereh noissim a dah llits ehS
.thgil teloivartlu ees ot ytiliba larutan reh hguorht neve elbisiv ylerab
?scinortcele sti htiw gnirefretni ereh gnihtemos saW
,nrettap a ekam ot demees senil ehT
,drawno deunitnoc dna dapatad reh dewots elpaM
.ecafrus ykcor ,pmad eht no esnopser on deticile pit sti no lairetam ekil-fooh kcalb ehT
”…mrots eht morf dleihs a sa snoitamrof enots eht raen pmac pu tes yeht ebyaM“
reh rednu yaw evag ylneddus senots ehT
.syad nihtiw raeppasid ot ylno noiger cificeps siht otni enog dah maet noitidepxe na ,oga sraey net taht dellacer ehS
.daehrevo delbmur rednuhT
.sknurt eert erab eht dehcaorppa ehs sa ecneserp reh htiw tuo gnihcaer
,llaw eht dnuora yaw reh gnikaM .llaw delbmurc ybraen a revo dehcaer ti erehw ot turts eht dewollof ehS
.regnad eht htrow erew seirevocsid laitnetop ehT
.daehrevo delbmur rednuhT
?krowenots gnilbmurc siht lla tsdimA ?cillatem ti saW
.erolpxe ylefas dna yltnedifnoc dluoc elpaM ,sdliw eht ni neve taht gnirusne
.ti evoba tsuj gnirevoh maets citsuac gnivael
,revaeW enuR a saw ehS
.detniojsid erew yeht tub
,dehsalf gninthgil nehw deraeppa snrettap eht hguohT
,egalliv llams a esolcne ot hguone egral saw tI
,tsiaw reh dnuora slaiv noitcelloc gnidloh stleb eht denethgit ,kaolc reh detsujda elpaM
.ruf reh gnikaos ruopnwod eht yb desahpnu
,emanresu emas eht rednu ytiniffAruF ta dnuof eb nac ohw
.niaga ecno derekcilf ylerem krowenots eht no snrettap eht tub
,dna koobgol reh tuo deppihw ehS
.seitilibissop wen pu denepo sihT
.flesti krowenots eht ot noitnetta reh denrut elpaM
,deraor rednuht dna dehsalf gninthgil sa detloj ehS
rebmemer dluoc ehs snrettap tahw tuo delbbircs ,niar eht morf ti dleihs ot ydob reh gnisu
.sulyts dna koobgol foorprehtaew a tuo gnillup
.flesreh retnec ot htaerb a koot elpaM
.nwod nrow dna dlo os ecalp a ni desu nehw hcum os od ylno yltnerappa dluoc
.demrifnoc demees snoicipsus reh ,renroc nekorb-flah a gnidnuoR
.yrwa tnew gnihtemos fi tseb ta yawa keew a netfo saw pleh erehw
.egaugnal a saw tI
.senil tiucric eht ni seitiralimis ynit etipsed
,ylfeirb reh gniltrats ,dehsalf gninthgiL
.no rehtruf ezah kciht-niar eht otni deraeppasid erutcurts eht erofeb gnir eht ffo detcelfer wolg gnirevaw ,gninekcis s’tip ehT
,swolg ydaets ni deslup senur ehT
.remmus fo elddim eht saw siht sa lausunU
.tnew ehs drawni rehtruf eht detadipalid erom gnimoceb saw aera eritne eht taht deraeppa ti ,dnuora lla gnicnalG
.ekirts gninthgil yreve htiw gnivom saw esle gnihtemoS .sniur eht gnikahs rednuht tsuj t’nsaw tI
.eunitnoc ehs taht deggeb dlroW dlO eht tuoba ytisoiruc elbaitasni reh dna
,aesuan egnarts a emac ti htiW
,detsur ton saw tI
,sdliW tiripS eht ni noitidepxe hcraeser a enoptsop ot nosaer elbaiv a erew smrots gnimocnI   2 fo
…stros fo erutcurtsbus a gnicneulfni eb wohemos yam mrots ehT
,ti dellac stuocs eht sa ,cigam tiripS
.erofeb emoc dah ohw yna ekilnu
,segassem lluf gnikaeps eb dluoc sdliW tiripS eht fo yteritne eht ,os fI
.neercs sti no deraeppa gnihton
.gnihton detceted niaga ecno tub
.niar dnim yllaer ton did eod ehT
.ereh krowenots eht ni sgnikram fo ecnedive saw erehT
,latem eht dnuora lla seceip derettahs ni saw krowenots ehT
,suileA yb ”revaeW enuR“
.ruopnwod eht otni tuo edorts ylluferac neht
.tip eht evoba raf tfola dleh
.ezah s’niar eht ni edis rehto sti ot ssorca ees neve ton dluoc ehs dna
.esolc saw pmac esab ,yalpsid cihpargoloh gnirekcilf eht no setanidrooc reh ot gnidroccA
.denruter reven osla ecnaraeppasid eht etagitsevni ot ni tnew taht puorg txen ehT
.ffuc tsirw reh no tuodaer cihpargoloh a morf setanidrooc fo tes a gniwollof
,reh emusnoc nac ti erofeb
.yletelpmoc ,emoh reh dna
.oot ,emit doog nI
.niar fo dnuos eht thguac ylno tub tuoba dennap srae reH
.reh tsniaga dednuop niar eht sa yromem ot ti timmoc ot deirt elpaM
.niaga ecneserp reh gnisucof ,llaw eht no dnah a decalp dna deleenk elpaM
.deklaw ehs sa krowenots eht gnola dnah reh devom ehS
.ydaerla ereh eb ot desoppus saw werc noitidepxe ehT
.niar esned yb deduorhs yllaudarg
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ecnadiug yna gnireffo tuohtiw ylkciuq sa tsuj dedaf tub
.sniur eht otni kcab dekool dna enots eht ffo dnah reh koot ehs sa delims eod ehT
,eciwt dehsilbup neeb osla sah eH
.dehsalf gninthgiL
.ria nepo eht otni dettuj latem erab
,efildliw fo sdnuos eht golatac ot dennap dna deleviws srae llaT
.no og ot erom dedeen ehS .koobgol eht wots dna hgis ylno dluoc ehs tub
,enots dekcarc fo seceip morf tuo gninnapS
8 RAOR dna stcA namuhnI ni
.hctap reraelc hcum a no desucof ehs sa gnitlit daeh ,deppots ehS
taerht suoiretsym siht tuo erugif ot seirt elpaM woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.daeh reh revo kaolc reh deggut ehs sa sucof ot gniyrt
.stnelat larutan rehto dah ehs ,ylikcuL
.ffo saw gnihtemos deciton seye neek reh tub
.ecart a tuohtiw deraeppasid ecno dah srossecederp rieht erehw snoiger gnirolpxe esoht ot lativ lliks A
.reilrae pu til taht snoitrop eht ot ralimis demees sngised eht
.rednuht fo elbmur rehtona retfa reh htaeneb snoitarebrever egnarts eht tlef dna
,sevooh reh rednu niaga pu til ylfeirb senil tiucriC
fitom ngised tnereffid yletelpmoc a saw krowlatem eht gniciton
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
deraeppa ylno yeht
,enots eht fo serutxet hguor eht ni pu gnithgil senil tniaf gniees
.tneicna erom neve eb ot deveileb serutcurts fo pot no tliub neeb yllaitnetop dah sniur dlroW dlO emos taht dezisehtopyh stroper gnituocs roirP
,dnuorg ykcor eht tsniaga dnah a decalp dna deleenk ehS
.eno ni lla tsitra dna ,nairotsih
,secnereffid eht tuo elzzup ot detpmetta ehs sa reh dniheb dekcilf liat reH
.no rehtruf snoitamrof enots deciton elpaM ,denehtgnerts niar eht sA
.pu til sniur eht nehw reilrae nees dah ehs esoht fo emos llacer ot deirt neht
sevooh reh ta krowenots tew eht ni derekcilf senil tniaF
.koobgol reh no snrettap eht yduts ot desuap elpaM
.senil eht tuo delbbircs ehs sa koobgol reh revo dehcnuh dna llaw a fo deniamer tahw deraen elpaM
.fo desopmoc saw mottob eht ta egduls yzoo eht yltcaxe tahw tuo erugif dluoc ehs erofeb yawa kool ot reh gnicrof
,sitnaltA weN ni srehpargotpyrc tseb eht fo eno saw ehS
.yrwa tnew syawla gnihtemoS
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ereht tuo gniog saw noitidepxe s’elpaM nosaer elos eht saw mrots eht emit siht ,revewoH
.stiucric ton erew esehT
.reh dniheb ssenredliw eht fo ytirailimaf gniraeppasid eht dnoyeb deregnil stnecs oN
.ria nepo tub gnihton saw ti dnoyeB
.ecaf s’elpaM otno tperc elims ynit A
.noitartsurf ni deffuh elpaM
.denodnaba neeb dah ecalp eht ecnis sraey fo sdnasuoht eht ni toor nekat evah esiwrehto dluow taht
,lehctas reh otni dehcaer dna dapatad reh dewots elpaM
.llef ehs sa gnikeirhs
.evisnopsernu deniamer ti tub
.enots eht no deraeppa esle gnihton tub
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.smrotsniar gnirud deraeppa ylno swolg eht ,revewoH
.nees eb ot deniamer llits esoprup eht ,teY
.ezorf neht dna llaw eht tsap devom ehS
.detnemgarf oot erew yehT
.elihw gnol a rof ria eht ot desopxe neeb dah ti fi sa ecafrus llud a tuo ekam dluoc ehs ,ti nwod gniliart niar htiw neve hguoht
.rednuht gnilbmur yb dewollof
,seye reh gninrub saw ti ekil tlef wolg eht fo thgis yrev ehT
,evoba gnahrevo ykcor eht ta pu decnalg elpaM   .enola saw ehS
.revewoh ,smrots fo edistuo evitcani demees noiger siht yhw nialpxe ton did tahT
.egailof kciht tsdima dnuorg tfos eht dort teef devooH
,no rehtruf sllaw delbmurc eb ot deraeppa tahw ees ot tuo dereep neht
.dnah reh fo kcab eht no pu til ylneddus enur detniap a ,krowenots dilos eht no dnah a htiW
.lluks reh ta gniraet keirhs gnizinoga
.snoicipsus reh demrifnoc niar eht tsdima sdnuos ro stnecs fo kcal dna ssenitpme evisavrep eht ,taht naht eroM
noitategev fo ngis on llits saw ereht ,skcarc dna seciverc nepo eht etipseD
.flesti etis hcraeser eht ta eb ot dah ti ,gnikrow pots ot tnempiuqe reh rof semit eht lla fO
.daeha pu gniworg deppots evah ot demees ssarg eht nevE
,ereh was ehs seno eht htiw pu hctam ton did sniur eht fo segde retuo eht morf dellacer ehs snrettap ehT
.gniwolg erew ydob reh no senur eht wonk ot meht nepo ot deen ton did ehS
,snrettap eht gninnacs ro esion eht gnizylana fo snaem yna gnikcaL
.yltnecer ereh neeb dah ydobyna taht ngis on saw erehT
,erehwyreve sdnuos gnilbmurc tniaf draeh llits ehS
,rennacs sti etavitca ot deirt dna tuo kcab dap atad reh dellup ehS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,efildliw fo sngis ron sdnuos on ,tneserp yreneerg oN
?tnemnorivne rieht otni desufni yeht stiucric eht nopu desab saw egaugnal s’dlroW dlO eht fi tahW
.renroc a dednuor ehS
.tuo deyalps rae na ,niaga delbmur rednuht sA
,mlap reh rednu pu til llaw enots eht no senil tniaf sa dehctaw elpaM
?ti htiw gnirefretni gnihtemos saw rO
”revaeW enuR“    yojne esaelP
.evoba sevael eht dnoyeb rednuht tnatsid gnihctac
.regnif a htiw enots eht deppat dna desuap ehS
.daehrevo sehcnarb derehtiw eht no niar fo rettap ydaets eht ylno
.woleb raf kool ot derad ehs sa ecnalab niatniam ot gniyrt ,deyaws elpaM
1 traP ,suileA yb
,seye reh denepo elpaM
.esae ta reh tup ton did llits taht ,revewoH
.retfa noos emac rednuht dna
,enots otni dehcte snrettap eht tuo dehcteks ylitsah ehs ,gnahrevo eht rednu niar eht fo tuO
.niaga esion gninord eht rof denetsil ehs
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.daD regdaB yldduC