”?gniwolg llits ti si
,doots neht ,egde eht ot gnola delwarc ylluferac ehS
.dezalb senur reh sa dekeirhs elpaM
”.lla retfa ,ti edam uoY“
.pu gnideeps yltnerappa saw ssecorp eht
.ytivac eht otni repeed reh tnes dna tcapmi no devac otno llef ehs gnihtyrevE
.enots ekil tlef krab ehT
.saera efas ot resolc gnidaerps neeb dah noitidepxe eht detpmorp taht swolg eht woh gninialpxe
.ffo gnillaf morf flesreh gnipeek
,woleb demaercs snoitanoser s’tip eht dna evoba degar mrots eht sA
.gel derujninu reh no thgiew reh lla gnittup
.daeh reh tsniaga srae reh gnihctulc dna hcnarb deifirtep eht gnippord ,yawa dekcab dna depsag elpaM
.niaga ecno ecneserp reh gnisucof ,seye reh desolc dna dnuorg eht ot sdnah reh desserp ehS
.noitulos eht saw ehS
,ti raen erehwyna eb ot truh ti hcum woh gniwonK
,ydob eritne reh hguorht tohs niap ehT
,emit siht ecived eht hguorht gnitanoser erew yeht tub
,tsol saw ti fI
,noitcart dnif ot gnilggurts ,renroc a dednuor ehs sa senots kcils no deddiks sevooh reH
,senur etacilper dluoc ehS
,ssecorp eht ni despalloc egdel ehT .ffo depael ehs
,ti woleB .detrap dna deppans dah gnir eht fo trap—
?reh morf ekat ti dluow hcum woh tsuj tuB
,sretsamerol ’sitnaltA weN yb rehtegot delbboc sdrocer lacirotsih eht derebmemer ehS
.reh dednilb tsomla yeht thgirb os gniwolg ydob reh no detniap senur eht deciton ehS
.amsaim citsuac s’tip eht drawot gnignulp reh gnidnes
.ekawa deknilb yliggorg ehs sa weiv otni emac sepahs dna demmid thgil ehT
.gnikcarc draeh ehs hguoht dleh enots ehT
.gninefaed sa tsuj saw ti ,dennap srae reh yaw hcihw rettam oN .maercs laerehte
,niaga delbmur etis ehT
.tip eht morf yawa gnitteg saw fo kniht dluoc ehs llA
.deilper dihcrO ”,mrots eht yb detuor erew eW“
.yltcerroc nward eb ot deraeppa senur eht dna
,tip eht dnuora llA
.senur derehpicednu ni devargne lla ,smaeb troppus dilos fo seires a eb ot deraeppa tI
.emirg htiw derevoc yllaitrap tiebla
ti morf ecnatsid ruoy peeK …dooG“
ecived sselluos a otni fles fo esnes tsepeed reh gnitcejorp ylbicrof won daetsni tub
.ecneserp reh desucof dna seye reh desolc neht ,derettum ehs
.lehctas reh gnihctulc ,sniur eht hguorht nar dna denrut elpaM
.deiduts eb dluoc ti litnu
,smra gnilbbow no pu dehsup ehs
,pu flesreh hsup ot gniyrt dna epols yddum eht gnihctulC
.noitaroireted morf deraps neeb dah gnihton dna
.reh morf rewop ward yllaciteroeht osla dluoc ti neht
.gnir eht ni dleif tnemniatnoc demussa eht etavitcaer dluow siht taht eetnaraug on llits saw ereht dna
.od ot evah dluow ti derugif ehs ,reh dniheb deohce hsarc rehtona dna delbmur rednuht sA
.ecalp dirroh siht ot noitidepxe na morf nruter reven dluow ,oot ,ehs taht aedi eht dedaerd ehS
.ssecorp eht ni ekorb yltnerappa gnir eht litnu yawa stroppus latem eht fo noitrop a nrot gnivah
kaerb laretil a saw ti
,ruopnwod eht ni degrus swolg neerg-hsiwolley eiree
.woleb gninruhc saw revetahw fo stceffe hsrah eht gnipacse fo sepoh ni ylwols-os-reve flesreh gniggard
,yawa stnemrag reh tsac dna kaolc dehcnerd reh denetsafnu ehs ,niar eht morf dedleihS
2 traP ,suileA yb
.evoba dehsalf gninthgiL
.gniwolg deunitnoc slobmys sti sa gnir eht no llits
.evoba hgih reh dehcaer llits stceffe sti ,deniatnoc saw ti ton ro rehtehW
,erutcurts eritne eht ssorca deralf thgil thgirB
.txetnoc dah won etis eht dnuora lla ssenitpme gnibrutsid ehT
.elddup ybraen a ni senur reh fo snoitcelfer til deciton neht ehS
.devirra yllanif dah maet noitidepxe eht taht gnizilaer
.dehsalf gninthgiL
.ssecorp eht ni meht morf wolg nedlog euqinu a gnitaerc dna rehtegot meht gnixim
,sllaw delbmurc erom tsap maeb ekil-turts latem a dehcaer ehS
.deklaw ehs sa retal stnemom dedaf tub
.delbmut ehs sa tuo deirc ehS
.yaw emas eht pu til ecived eht sa kcab reh hcra ot reh gnicrof
.smrotsniar ni gniraeppa swolg suoiretsym fo seires a etagitsevni ot sniur tneicna fo etis a ta devirra reed eht elpaM
,yaw evag sniur eht ot derohcna stroppus eht nehw ,nehT
was dna egdel eht ot klaw suoituac a devarb ehS
.gnieb rehtona ot tcennoc ot elba eb neve reven dluohs
.epols evisorroc ,yddum s’tip
,swoble dna sdnah reh no drawrof devohs ehS
.sdliW eht ni stroper tuocs yb dedivorp seiroeht erew yb og ot dah yeht tahw fo tsom hguoht
.krowenots eht no daerps skcarC
.dlrow eht htiw gnitcaretni fo yaw euqinu a dah ydaerla ecneserp reh dna
.ydob nwo reh tsuj htiw ti gnitcennoc
.denworf neht ,knurt eht no dnah a decalp dna pu emac ehS
.tip eht evoba dleh gnir latem eht no slobmys eht fo erom tuo gnihcteks
.snaem nwonknu yb flesti deyortsed dah
.ecafrus tew eht no deppils sevooh reh dna gnidnal reh dehctob ehs ,koohs edis rehto eht sa tub
,seye reh ni gnitteg niar eht tuohtiw drawpu ecnalg ylerab dluoc elpaM
.morf deretne dah ehs dnuorg rehgih eht ot yaw rehtona rof dehcraes ehS
8 RAOR dna stcA namuhnI ni ,eciwt dehsilbup neeb osla sah eH
.dehca ydob eritne reH
.etis eht tuohguorht daerps esoht htiw tcaretni dluoc yeht deilpmi sngised enur s’gnir ehT
.tsael ta ,yroeht nI
!gnivom s’ehS“     .til llits saw
.ytilibats sti tset ot emit on saw erehT
.reh decarbme yltneg tibbar ehT
.dnim reh ni deraeppa noitulos a sa knas traeh reH
.tip eht gnilcricne
,sraey rof etis eritne eht gniruoved neeb dah tip ehT
ni llef ylraen ehs tip eht evoba degnarra neeb dah yeht erehw was ehs ,yllaniF
.maeb troppus delgna na hcaer ot ecnatsid hguone dah ehs tub
.denesrow yaced eht sa gnidaerps dna ti dnuora gnihtyreve gniruoved saw flesti tip eht taht demees ti ,ereht nwod saw revetahw gnitavargga eb ot deraeppa niar sA
,gnir nekorb eht fo edis rehto eht no sdnah htob ecalp ot drawrof llaf flesreh tel dna kaerb eht ssorca tuo dehcaer ehs ,yllaniF
,edis reh ot dellor ylluferac ehS
,stnanmer esoht fo eno saw tip eht noitpmussa eht naht noitanalpxe rehto on fo kniht dluoc elpaM
.ydob dalcnu reh otno senur detsetnu
.tnemom gnissap yreve htiw denesrow ogitrev gninekcis sa elbirroh erom eht lla edam
,taht naht eroM .kcis tlef elpaM
ot deirt elpaM   ”.eguh
,ecived tnemniatnoc a deedni saw ti fI
.daeha erutcurts troppus s'gnir eht was dna
.esnopser ni gnihton tlef ehs ,erofeb sa tsuj ,tuB
.did I …seY“ .delims ehS
”!su llet d’uoy gnipoh erew eW“
.evoba nees dah ehs erutcurts emas eht fo trap saw ti deciton dna revo decnalg ylevitcnitsni ehS
.daeh s’reed eht gnildarc
.detcepxe naht retsaf nwod gnimoc erew sniur ehT
.slaiv fo oirt a tuo dellup dna lehctas reh ta deleenk neht
.kcab dehcaer dnik yna fo efil oN
…dna senur gnitaeper fo seires a evah ot demees tI“ .dihcrO dias ”,peY“
.dettirg hteet ,tnew ehs sa niap prahs ni detarbiv lluks reH
.gnivrennu saw ssecorp ehT
.daerps s’noisorroc eht pots dluoc elpoep reh yaw on saw ereht neht
”?taht htiw od ot gnihtemos evah uoy did ,tiaW
”.esnetni gnihtemos hguorht neeb ev’uoy ekil kool uoY“
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
.tnemezama ni deknilb dna dehcaorppa elpaM
,relevart wollef ruoy ,flowcaM boR si sihT
.spsag reh rof evas ,sselnoitom ereht yal elpaM   .krad
.evom erad ton did ehs
.niarb reh ta dewalc snoitanoser gnineddam s’tip ehT
,hcamots reh no delttes dna ecafrus denettalf eht no dellor elpaM
,ecap reh deps ylgnizinoga elpaM
ot seton dleif reh dekcehc ehS
gnir nekorb eht taht saw
.noitadnuof sti ssorca raf oot daerps yaced eht litnu ecived eht derewop evah tsum osla shpylg s’etis eht derewop revetahW
.egduls gniwolg eht ta kool neve ot truh tI
.gel derujninu reh no gnilbbow
.evres reve dluoc ecalp siht esoprup tahw enimreted ot gniyrt
,tnereffid ylddo saw tI
,dezilacol neeb dah noitalosed fo tpecnoc yrev eht fi sa saw tI
,niaga snoitarebrever eht tlef elpaM
segdel eligarf htiw dedilloc ehs sa snoitcerid lla morf elpaM gnikirts
,dettirg hteet ,nehT
.ecafrus gnilbmurc eht morf eciwt dloh tsol ylno ylluficrem tub
”…emit oN“
.evael ot dah ehS
.ytpme dna etalosed saw aera eritne ehT
,dihcrO dias ”,tey evom dna yrt t’nod ,yeh-yeH“
,niar eht hguorht yaw reh edam reed eht sa wolg ot deunitnoc senur ehT
.ruf dekaos nwo reh tub gnihton ni dehtolc won
.ezah eht ni ffo raf erutcurts eht ni kaerb a deciton elpaM ,ekaw sti ni detsalb rednuht sa dna ,evoba dehsalf gninthgiL
”…lla uoy llet ot tol a tog ev’I
.yrellag sih ni krowtra dna seirots htob gniwohs
.despalloc dna dekcarc egdir enots ybraen A   .deraor rednuhT
.ti fo sretem wef a nihtiw teg ylerab dluoc eW“
riaper yraropmet a mrofrep tsael ta ot yaw a eb ot dah ereht
.tsrif ti deyortsed yaced eht fi yllaicepse
.dnuof ehs gnahrevo tsrif eht rednu gnippots ,sniur gniyaced eht hguorht kcab deirruh ehS
.yawa retem a naht ssel saw kaerb ehT
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht saw sihT
.evoba hgih tip eht gnilcricne erutcurts ekil-gnir evissam a—
.dnoyeb dna segdel eht tsap yaw eht lla sturts troppus rieht dna smaeb eht dewollof ezag reH
,oga gnol yawa nekorb dah senots erehw tops a morf gniworG !eert a saw tI
.gninruter yllaudarg ssensuoicsnoc ,decniw ehS .seye s’elpaM ni denihs thgil thgirB   ”!pu gnikaw s’ehS
.ylkaew deksa ehs ”?deneppah tahW“
,ti etacilper ot woh tuo gnirugif enola tel ,ygolonhcet fo dnik siht gniriaper fo yaw on dah
,htaerb reh hctac ot desuap dna hcamots reh ot devom ehs sa ria rof detnap elpaM   .til
,pu yaw reh edam ylidaets ehS
…desimorpmoc saw erutcurts troppus eht fo eceip rehtona fi dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.pag s’gnir eht egdirb neht dna no meht tniap ot gnihtemos saw dedeen ehs llA
.niar eht ni swolg detroper eht fo ecruos eht eb ot dah sihT
erofeb naht rethgirb derekcilf senil tiucric ,sevooh s’elpaM woleB
.ti no thgiew tup ot elbanu
,seirraH nomoloS yb daer
,no desserp ehs ,teY
,delrang ylsuodnerroh saw dna sevael on dah eert eht
.niur a deredisnoc ydaerla erew sniur eht retfa detcurtsnoc saw ti
.detisiv dah ehs ecalp rehto yna naht nerrab erom erew sniur ehT
,til deniamer senur reH
,dehctiwt selcsum reh dna ,dael ekil tlef kaolc reH
.ytefas ot uoy llup ot uoy hcaer t’ndluoc tsomla ryhpeZ
.ecalp siht morf denruter reven taht snoitidepxe rehto eht ot deneppah tahw enigami ylno dluoc elpaM
.gnibmilc yrt ot evoba egdel a fo hguone tuo ekam dluoc tub
,tlah a ot gniddiks litnu dellor dna enilcni tfos a tih ehs ,yllaniF
.sisehtopyh rehtona rehtegot deceip ehs
.shtaerb tuo-nward ,gnol htiw sdnah reh ydaets ot deirt elpaM ,toofrednu deslup snoitarebrever erom sA
,sseworp cifitneics sti etipsed ,sitnaltA weN taht noitazilaer eht ta depsag ehS
,gnimaercs tpek elpaM
.delkcuhc dna seye reh desolc elpaM
.gnitnap ,ti tsniaga denael dna llaw dekcarc a dehcaer ehS
,won detsixe ti sa dlroW weN eht ot htrib evag ylgnittiwnu snaem emas esohT
.knurt eht ni eloh gnitluser eht morf tuo dellips diulf neerg-wolley gninekcis emas eht sa srae reh kcurts noitanoser prahs a tub
.erom ecno sevooh reh rednu rekcilf ot senots eht ni shpylg tiucric eht gnisuac
.daeh reh fo gnibborht eht ni ybraen dellews thgil esnetni sa dereffus noisiv reh nevE
,dednopser eciov eninimef ,railimaf A
!erif ekil tlef yehT
.eroc sti morf drawtuo etis eritne eht gnidorroc ylidaets neeb dah tip eht fi sa reh dnuora lla llef dna delbmurc senots eroM
,yb og ot krowsseug detacude dah ylno ehs ,revewoh ,shpylg eseht roF
.evoba degar mrots eht elihw lla
.reh htiw seceip gnikat dna gnilbmut elihw
.ecap reh deps ehS
,sniur enots eht dna ti neewteb ngised lacigolonhcet ni tfihs ehT
.reh gnidnuop deunitnoc niar eht sa dum ni derevoc
.morf nur dah ehs erehw ot kcab decnalg elpaM
,ecived tnemniatnoc fo tros emos neeb evah tsum gnir ehT
.erutcurts gnir nekorb eht no desucof elpaM
.gnikool peek ot emit on saw erehT
,dnats ot gnivloseR
.flesreh ot derettum elpaM
.evig on saw ereht tub ,deggut dna hcnarb a debbarg ehS
,dehsalf gninthgiL
,stceffe s’tip eht gnitavargga mrots eht htiw dna
.yawa rehtruf depmil dna thgirpu dereggats ylwols neht
.hcuot reh rednu ylfeirb derekcilf ecafrus sti ta senil tiucriC
.dehcuot ti gnihtyreve gniruoved yltnapmar dna denekawa
,mlap reh otni stnetnoc eht deruop dna meht denepo ehS
.htiw senur tniap ot slairetam war dah llits ehS
,gninesrow ogitreV
,enots elttirb eht otni sregnif deppit-fooh reh debbaj ehs ,tfel dah ehs htgnerts tahw gniretsuM
,tnew ehs sa enots fo snoitrop ffo gniraet
.ezah evisorroc eht evoba ehtaerb ot saw ti sa tluciffid
,ydob reh no secalp thgir eht ni dekram erew icoF .thgir demees gnihtyrevE
.tip evisorroc ,evissam a revo detautis erutcurts latem egnarts a htiw gnola
.daerps dluoc ti ylkciuq woh gnillet on saw ereht ,noos deniatnoc ton saw ti fI
.yawa hsaw ton did senur eht tub
.maeb eht debmilc ylwols ehs
…no em dnuof uoy erutcurts tahT
.reed eht dias ”…dihcrO“
,rednuht tnatsid dna llafniar draeh ehS
,koobgol reh dekcehc dna pu kaolc reh dellup elpaM
,sllaw detaroced fo stnanmer dna
.ydob reh hcnerd ot deunitnoc niar eht sa dehguoc ehS
,epols eht nwod sretem ereM
…fo kcohs eht morf gnileer
”.ereht nwod s’tahw tuo derugif t’nevah llits eW
,kcab deppets elpaM sa tub ,raf mees ton did pag s’gnir ehT
,ytilaer fo noitpecrep yreve ni ,taht
elbbur fo dnuom a tsap nar elpaM
,ti otno flesreh devohs dna egdel eht dehcaer ehs ,yllanif ,nehT
.kaerb s’gnir eht hcaer ot maeb troppus a bmilc dluoc ehs erehw tniop tsesolc eht dellacer yleugav elpaM ,reh tsniaga gnidnuop niar htiW
daD regdaB yldduC
,kcab reh no dednal dna drawkcab nworht saw elpaM
.gnizeehw ,hcamots reh otno kcab despalloc tub evom ot pu dehsup ylkaew ehS
,dnim reh otni decreip dnuos eht fi sa saw tI
sniur eht tuohguorht dnuof esoht morf
,ydob reh nwod dedacsac niar eht sa sngised eht morf drawpu delruc ygrene fo spsiw yniT
.ybraen deggaj gnihtemos dethgilhgih gninthgil litnu tuoba gnitrad seye
,niaga dehsalf gninthgiL   .ti htiw ekorb
.ereht nwod saw revetahw
.drawpu yaw a rof yletarepsed dehcraes ehs sa llaw eht gnigguh ot flesreh detageler dna nwod kool ot raeb ton dluoc ehS
,sniur eht fo yrtiucric peed eht morf rewop sti werd gnir eht fI
.elims deveiler ylesnemmi na gniraew
?sraey fo sdnasuoht retfa nekawa ot ti desuac tahw ,neht oS
.niap ni tuo gniyrc
,yromem tnatsid a erew sniur eht erofeb gnol eb t’ndluow tI
,noiger eht gnitcefni saw tip taht ni dniheb tfel ecnatsbus dlroW dlO revetahW
.denruter ogitrev gninekcis s’tip ehT
,gnir eht morf deipoc sngised enur eht mrifnoc
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitcelfer reh ni krow reh kcehc ot elddup ybraen a ot revo decnalg elpaM
ti gnirewop tiucric eht dna deppans gnir eht
.eceip rotcennoc tfihsekam a gnitfarc fo sepoh ni
,maeb eht dnuora smra reh depparw dna latem yreppils eht no drah dednal ehS
”revaeW enuR“    yojne esaelP
,ecneserp s’eno ot detcaer yeht woh gniwonk tuohtiw senur ylppa reve dluow dnim thgir rieht ni eno oN
,dnats ot deirt dna decniw ehS
.ecrof eht detpurretni dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,noisorroc s’tip eht yb devlossid neeb ylgnimees dah krowenots eht ni hsag a
dneherpmoc dluoc ehs gniht tsal ehT
,deddon dna htaerb a tuo tel ehS
.dlohdnah yratnemidur a ekam ot hguone gnikcarc
.krowlatem ybraen ffo detcelfer gninthgil tnatsiD
.tceffe dednetni rieht etacilper ot ecneserp reh htiw meht etavitca dna
.niatnuof a ekil knurt eht morf tuo dellips egduls ehT
tibbar elamef derae-pol a gniees ,eciov eht ot denrut elpaM
,revocer I retfa esuaceb
.ygrene emas eht morf etavitca ot tnaem llits saw ti teY
.seenk reh ot tog dna ,no debmilc ,gnir eht dehcaer yllanif ehS
.deniamer llits yhw fo noitseuq ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.sdeen reh evres dluoc ti tub
.denesrow daeh reh ni snoitanoser eht dna ,seye reh sucof ylerab dluoc ehS
,etis eritne eht gnirevoc shpylg tneicna gnirevocsid
.yletelpmoc reh niard dna
,deohce sehsarc eroM
…yllanif litnu gniyfisnetni
.reilrae stnemom deiduts dah ehs esoht no desab snrettap nedlog gniziremsem ni ydob reh gnirevoc ,pu til senur wen ehT
.elacs ot retawniar morf kcils oot saw ti tub
.ecnesse yrev reh ta erot ti sa tip eht morf yawa
.niap ni decamirg tub pu nael
.sdliW tiripS suoregnad ,evisnapxe eht ni gniregnil llits are tsap eht fo stnanmer htiw tiebla
.delffum ylkciuq neht ,sniur eht ssorca deohce hsarc rehtonA
,drawpu delwarc dna epols eht no nwod depmuls ehS
,emit tsaL  .tenalPruF yb
.tilnu tub ,ruf reh no detniap llits senur eht gniciton
tuo gnikcalb erofeb
,neppah thgim revetahw ot flesreh gnivloser
…dluow ti depoh ehs tahw ylesicerp od dluow noitavitcaer taht ytilibissop laer eht saw oslA
.retawdnuorg eht detartenep dah tI
.tniopkaerb s’gnir eht tcennocer wohemos dluoc ehs fi ecived tnemniatnoc eht tratser ot yaw a eb yllaciteroeht dluohs erehT
.daeha egdel a tsap gnir nekorb eht was ehs ,sraet dekaos-niar hguorhT
.deifisnetni snoitarebrever dna
,despalloc no doots ehs krowenots eht ,rehtruf erolpxe dluoc ehs erofeB
.ybraen sesion gnilbmurc erom yb dewollof
eht otni despalloc dah seceip fi sa delffum neht
.daehrevo dehsarc rednuht sa thgil eht drawot ecnalg a devarb ehs
…senur gnitaeper eht
snmuloc enots nekorb tsap deunitnoc dna ecnalab deniatniam ehs tub
.dilos deifirtep neeb dah tI
,deunitnoc elpaM ”…tip eht dnA“
,tsud tub gnihton emoceb dah trid dna enots
,evoba dellor rednuht sA
.no deirrac ehs tub ,denruhc hcamots reh sa daeh reh ni debborht esion suodnerroh railimaf ehT
.tsrif esu ot tcejbo na gnidnif retfa derewsna eb ot evah dluow tiucric sti etelpmoc ot woh fo noitseuq ehT
,kaerb eht revo depael ehs dna reh fo daeha senots eht tilps kcarc A
,suileA yb ”revaeW enuR“
.ylfeirb derekcilf senur s’ecived ehT
,doots ylluferac dna egdir dekcarc eht dehcaer ehs ,yllaniF
.ogitrev reh etipsed ffo llaf ot ton tseb reh gniyrt
,azalp ytpme na hguorht nar ehS
,emanresu emas eht rednu ytiniffAruF ta dnuof eb nac ohw ,suileA yb
.yawa dekcab ehs sa denediw seye s’elpaM
,woleb morf emac hsarc A
.yltneuqerf detaeper dna
.denediw seye s’dihcrO
.reh gnihcnerd deunitnoc ruopnwod eht sa ria rof gnipsag llits
”?uoy did ,ti ot resolc tnew uoy fo enoN“
.delwarc ehs sa htaerb rof gnipsag ,niaga dehguoc ehS
.daD regdaB yldduC
.skcor fo gnilbmurc ron snoitarebrever on tub
.aesuan gnitaicurcxe reh etipsed sgniraeb reh niag ot gniyrt
.tuo evag eciov reh retfa neve pots ot elbanu
.dluoc ehs sa tsaf sa gnilwarc
.dnah rehto reh htiw niaga baj ot htgnerts eht gninommus ,drawpu devohs dna detnurg ehS
.htgnerts eht retsum ton dluoc tub ,niaga deirt ehs sa repmihw ylkcis a tuo tel ehS
,mra ylbbow a pu dleh elpaM
.ruopnwod eht otni kcab deppets dna
.evoba delbmur rednuht sa erom ecno ecneserp reh desucof dna seye reh desolc reed ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.emoh reh evas ot troffe na retfa eb dluow ti gniwonk trofmoc fo mucidom a dnuof ehs ,tsael yrev eht ta ,llitS
ydob reh no stniop sucof thgir eht no sngised enur egnarra ot woh dnatsrednu ot hguone elbaegdelwonk saw elpaM
,dehguoc reed ehT
,elbaraebnu na emoceb dah enord gnitarebrever a
.won dnim reh ni tbuod on saw erehT
,tnereffid llits tub ,ralimis erew slobmys ehT
,saw erutcurts siht revetahW
.ybraen erehwyna gnitsixe efil on htiw
,efil htiw tnadnuba tnemnorivne na ot ton pu flesreh gninepo
,etelpmoc ssecorp ehT
.reh no nwod taeb niar eht sa yawa deppihc seceip enotS
.egduls yzoo na ekil ylmodnar dellews yeht sa thgil htiw gnitaslup
.dekcik yltfiws dna hcnarb eht dehctulc elpaM
daehrevo tsrub gninthgil litnu sevaw gnitaicurcxe ni reh hguorht desruoc rewop ehT
.htaerb a koot dna doots neht
,dekcilf srae s’elpaM
,reed sselpah eht dnuora lla nups dlrow ehT   2 fo
.efil reh gniksir tnaem ti fi neve ,daerps eht pots ot enod eb ot dah gnihtemoS
.niaga deraor rednuht dna
.meht evoba derevaw prat savnac tfihsekam A
,toof reh gnihctulc dnuorg eht ot kcab llef neht tub
.yrruh ot dah ehS
,yawa deppans ti dna hcnarb eht hguorht debbaj sevooh hguot reH
.tip eht ot resolc deunitnoc sesion gnilbmurc sa drawrof dennap srae s’elpaM
,gninnur emac dna wolg eguh a deciton eW“
.uoy ot thgir dewollof dna tnecs ruoy thguac ew nehw s’taht dna
.niap gnitaicurcxe ni elkna reh htiw tlah a ot dellor ehS
.no detniap eb dluow yeht ydob eht fo aera eht tceffa dluow yeht woh enola tel
,enola sdeecorp ehs ,ereht teem ot desoppus saw ehs maet noitidepxe eht fo ngis on htiW
”revaeW enuR“ fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
deyats gnir eht ,os nevE
gnitteg saw gnihtyrevE
.woleb snoitanoser gninekcis eht morf debborht daeh reh dna dehca ydob reH
gnihtemos …no tuo dessap d’uoY
,snmuloc gniyaced tsap dna rodirroc nerrab a nwoD
.ytirgetni s’gnir eht desimorpmoc ti ,noitadnuof s’etis eht dehcaer yaced eht nehw tub
elbissop sa slobmys enur s’gnir eht fo sliated ynam sa rebmemer ot gniyrt ,decar dnim reH
.dnuora lla noisuffid gninekcis eht ni rehtruf gnilbmut morf flesreh thguac tub ylisaenu deyaws elpaM
,wen detniap ylluferac dna noitulos gniwolg eht otni regnif deppit-fooh a desserp ehS
.deifisnetni snoitarebrever gnitaesuan llits dna railimaf s’tip eht
erofeb emac taht dlroW dlO eht taht saw feileb nommoc a ,llitS
.ti leef ot bmun oot saw ehS
”…od ot tuoba m’I tahw ees dluoc enoyna fI“