.ot naem t'ndid I"
.noisserppO dnE ot eettimmoC eht fo noisses siht redro ot gnirb I"   lerdnaK yb
.nibac sih dna senirtal eht neewteb diov yci eht ssorca decar yevaD ,rewohs sih morf tew llits ruf sih htiW
"stekcaj efil era ereht ,lleW"
tserrufniaR pmaC suoirolg ruo evas lliw ew taht raews od
.tnuoc ti ekam ot ecnahc sih saw won dnA
.emit siht thgir ti od dna kcab oG
,htap eht fo eercs esool eht no deddiks teef siH
.deed eliv a ylurT" "!yllub tahT"
.won etal oot saw ti tub ,nwonk d'eh fi pu dengis evah t'ndluow eH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.niaga pu ekops aramaT ,yllaniF
,deggurhs yevaD ".eniF"
.ti rof esle gnihtoN
,tiag derusaem a htiW
noisserppO dednE taht eettimmoC demrof-ylwen eht ,revewoH"
.erofeb yad eht dna ,oot ,yadretsey delwocs d'eH
.cinap a ni dnuora denrut yevaD
.snevetS rolesnuoC seY"
.dessap eh sa yrctuo na otni detpure srepmac dekcohS
.enil etalosnocsid a ni dewollof dna ,eno-yb-eno
txen eht ot ytivitca suorutnevda eno morf ylsuoiriled dezzihw yeht sa srepmac fo sgniyrrucs deiznerf ehT
.snevetS rolesnuoC eliv eht fo sehctulc eht morf tserrufniaR pmaC suoirolg ruo evas lliw-"
.stnerap sih llac ot deen on s’erehT
.yltnassecni dehctiwt sreksihw esohw lerriuqs suovren a gnilaever
.nahoR ta kool ot lias eht dnuora enarc ot dah yevaD ".em hsuP"
,etirw ot dedeen I tahw em dlot uoY
tnemtaert fo dnik tnereffid emos dednamed slrig taht dezilaer eh erehw ega eht dehcaer yltnecer tsuj dah regoR
.mih ot ECIN tca ot dah eh naem t'ndid taht tub
.nahoR emoclew ot enoyreve ekil d'I
.ecaf a llup ot desuap regoR ".lla
.suoregnad erew snalP
meht ta delwocs snevetS rolesnuoC
ot nesir dah edistuo erutarepmet eht dna
,nalp a saw nalp a tuB
,retaw eht no tuo morF
.lufecaep tsomla demees pmac eht
,moorhtab eht otni dedecer eh sA
.lluh s'taoblias erutainim eht ni selddap eht fo seldnah eht gnoma teef erab sih gnilddif
"?cilbup ni ereh tuo ,won thgiR"
.snevetS rolesnuoC fo liart eht dewollof skeirhs ,ecnatsid eht ni ffO
.skraps tnarre wef a gniworht dna
.ytsedom ruoy tuohtiw sdnuorgpmac ym no uoy evah ton lliw I ,snevetS .rM"
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.thgilhsalf eht fo eralg eht otni drawrof denael eh sa detniuqs regoR
,dworc eht morf drawrof deppets nahoR ,mih ot txeN
.tsdim rieht otni delworp ehs sa
,lias eht delruf dna
.deedni tca eliv a saw taht
tekcar lanrefni sih htiw pmac eht ekow snevetS rolesnuoC
nirg erihsehc a dennirg yevaD ".egdelp
,stnemom tnacs rof dengier ecneliS ".eromyna
.nalp doog a eb retteb sihT"
.ylreporp ffo deird evah dluohs uoy nehT"
.kcod eht ta deroom ylippols saw ti erehw morf
.rewohs eht morf paos htiw demaof llits dna
"!nahoR ,uoy hctac ot gniog m'I"
.atsap deird dna ,etsap
".eman nwo rieht esu ot sevresed ereh enoyrevE
,thgilhsalf paehc a fo wolg eht dnuora derehtaG
stnialpmoc fo ynohpocac gninrom ehT
.sraef dna sepoh sih demrifnoc ecnalg enO
-- desserpmi saw eettimmoc ehT "!?ytriht eviF"
.ria gninrom digirf eht tem ti erehw
"!mood fo tepmurt ehT"
,oga gnol neeb t'ndah tesnus ehT
.yart sih pu dekcip yevaD ".uoy
.flesmih ot thguoht yevaD ,detrats elbuort eht erehw saw ereH
.nahoR retfa erot flow detnemrag-ed eht sa
,thgis eht ta derettacs srepmaC
.laeuqs tnangidni na ot esor tsal ehT "!gninrom eht ni
,ruf sih fo tuo mucs-dnop dekcip dna
,gniliaS fo trats eht ta nesohc erew seiddub nehw oS
.ereh ton m'I ekil em tuoba klat ot evah t'nod uoY"
mir s'taob eht deppirg eH
"?I t'ndid ,nalp a dah I dias I !ydaerla em hsuP"
.noonretfa tnasaelp eht tpurretni dluoc lias eht gnibrutsid ezeerb dlim eht ylno dna ,liuqnart
"!tarb elttil uoy ,efil ruoy fo yad tsrow eht siht ekam ot gniog m'I raews I !ereh kcab teG"
.tuohs eht ecaf ot denrut ylwols yevaD
,dekan saw snevetS rolesnuoC
.etispmac eht fo retnec yrev eht denroda taht elopgalf eht ot dehcram eh sa
.hcnul sih fo tsal eht dehsinif eh sa
,dnif d'eh tahw gnidaerD
.srae suoixna revo kcab nward gnieb sdooh htiw
".tepmurt taht swolb dna
.laiciffo yrev dednuos tI
,noisserppO dnE ot eettimmoC eht fo srebmem eht ,eW"
.esion detcepxenu yreve ta ylsuovren depmuj srotaripsnoc detcelloc eht sa
.tohsnug a ekil tsorf gninrom eht hguorht erot tuohs ehT "!yevaD"
,llew( dlo dna gnuoy ,srepmac erom dna eroM
.seye sih dellor yevaD
.ereh steg rotcerid eht litnu ereh tis ot gniog er'uoY"
retaw eht revo tuo dehcterts
,nwod deknay saw dooh deid-eit ehT
.ydnac eht fo srepeek eht no regnif a yal erad eno oN
"...hU ...dnA ...dna aramaT lleT"
,egnar eht no nwod yrehcra nehT
,deteiuq seciov rehto lla ,gnilley saw rotcerid eht nehW
.rehto hcae ta dennirg aramaT dna ,yevaD ,nahoR ,regoR elihw
.reh ot klat yllautca ot detnaw eno on tub ,gninnigeb eht ta hceeps gninepo eht evag ehs nehw deppalc dna delims lla yeht ,erus ,hO
nibac sih ot yaw sih edam dna
.sdooh rof mraw oot
.demrof neeb dah eettimmoC eht ecnis dah srehto eht fo yna naht erom saw ti dna
.rebmem tnarticlacer eht ta decnalg eh sa
.won kcod ot ni ,uoy fo llA"
dooh gnilaecnoc s'yevaD nihtiw morf denihs saniter evitcelfeR "?tahW"
.ereht dedne stnialpmoc eht tub
.detpurretni saw elbmahs wols sih tub
ellieveR fo laticer gninrom eht htiw tod eht no thgie ytnewt xis ta ylpsirc nageb yad ehT ----- ".dedne
deksa nahoR "?5 nibaC dniheb ,niaga thginoT"
,elbat eht morf yawa deklats yevaD ".oot
,nesohc neeb dah esle enoyreve litnu tiaw ot dah xof elttil eht yllausU
.aramaT ,selur eht wonk uoY"
.miws t'nac uoY ?yzarc uoy erA"
dworc eht hguorht dehtycs rotcerid eht fo eciov llirhs ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,lerdnaK yb
.ecafrus eht htaeneb tsuj gniliob
,srossics htiw srednow krow dluoc ohw raeb ylnortam a
.hcni na evom erad uoy t'nod ,yevaD"
.ecnalutep sih deniatniam tub
.elzzum yddur s'xof elttil eht fo tsom gnidih
.rolesnuoc eht fo noinipo rieht tnemec rehtruf ot devres ylpmis sihT .deddon yehT
.srolesnuoC eht neve evoba saw ehs dna
,dloc nar retaw toh eht erofeb srewohs barg ot senirtal eht ot derepmacs
.psag evitcelloc a saw erehT ".sdne
,lwocs detaefed a htiW ".niaga
".ti naem I ,em hsuP"
elgub nit paehc a no
.gninrom eht fo emit desruc siht ta etairporppa morf raf
,niaga flesti degnarraer puorg ehT
,mih denioj aramaT .detulas dna
,nosrep lamron eht naht
!yevaD" -rof dehsinup eb ot gniog eh saw yhw os
kcohs tcejba ni dehctaw neht
.pmac eht hguorht dekan gniklats rolesnuoc reh dnuof ehs sa rotceriD eht fo noitamalcxe llirhs eht yb detpurretni erew yehT
.yadot rebmem wen a evah ev'ew ,woN"
.ffo deliart ehS "...rrE ...hhha tahT"
noisserppO dnE ot licnuoC eht fo daeh eht fo ecnuo yreve detca eh
.egdelp eht kaeps ,regoR"
.teg ot gniog saw ti sa efas sa ro ,efas erew yehT
desrever d'eh emit eht yb dna
sresal ybur ekil gnihsalf seye
.noisserppo dnE ot eettimmoC eht fo egaugnal reporp ehT"
,shtped eht morf esor dna
dehcnerd ruf yarg
,evilO .srM eht htiw stfarc dna stra neht ,tsafkaerb emac eludehcs s'yad eht no tsriF ".elbarelot"
rettum mih draeh yevaD
.lrig eht ta kool yrgna na werht xof elinevuj a dna
.yevaD revo dehtacs yeht sa
.egdelp eht gnitaeper llits ,regoR neht
decnalg nahoR ,mih dniheB ".yevaD ,tsssP"
noisiv sih detnit egar deR
,selddap detuorps staoblias erutainim eht dna
.sdrow s'rolesnuoC eht fo tsal eht ffo gnippilc
.sgnidliub noitartsinimda ybraen eht fo ffo deohce tuohs s'rotcerid ehT ".snevetS
.redluohs sih ot hcuot evitatnet a tlef eh
tsaot sih ta delwocs yevaD
.krad retfa tsuj 5 nibac dniheb gniteem eb lliw
.keirhs a yb niaga detpurretni saw eH "-lliw ew taht raews od
.snevetS yb nur erew ekal eht no tuo strops lla dna
.llorts ylerusiel ,tnedifnoc a ni
flesmih ot thguoht yevaD ,mih nmaD
".ecno ta flesruoy revoC
,kcordeb desopxe eht no drah nwod dnah sih ni enots eht thguorb yevaD ".noisserppO
,kcab eht ta reddur esool eht dennam eh sa delwocs yevaD ".miws
"?nahoR rebmem eettimmoc roinuj ,lla taht sI"
.tnatsid teef derdnuh a erew yeht hguoht neve
.yralubacov reh fo retrauq a liatruc ot dah d'ehS
”galF eht etulaS“ saw sihT
enileert eht evoba detserc dah nus eht
.hctaw ot elopgalf eht raen derehtag )redlo tsael ta
,niaga dnuora decnalg xof ehT ".tey toN" "?yppaH
.elzzum sih morf derettuts lworg wol a dna
.snevetS rolesnuoC fo dnah yarg-leets eht yb stnemom tsuj ni dewollof
,kcab repmuj sih fo dooh eht gnulf regoR ".diputs s'tI"
detabanu deeps ,htaptoof levarg eht no delbmuts dna dils teef siH
.gniht nmad eht etorw uoY .regoR ,toidi na eb t'noD"
.sehtolc pmac remmus suoirav rieht tsgnoma
.retaw nepo eht sdrawot derednaem ylwols staoblias eht
,gnilias saw txeN
,kcod ot kcab ,thgiR"
tuhs seye sih dewercs dah xof elttil ehT
.sdne pmac litnu rekcol pmac eht ni dleh gnieb lla s'ti taht dna
dehsilbup yllanigiro saw yrots ehT
ehs sA ".rotcerid eht hctef oG"
.eciffo ym ot yletaidemmi troper lliw uoy neht dna ,flesruoy revoc ot gnihtemos dnif lliw uoy ,snevetS .rM"
,xof elttil eht deillub reven d'eH ?siht evresed ot enod eh
"...hu ,I ,ylirev od I ,seY"
.noitnetta etaidemmi dednammoc taht eciov elamef hcir a
.niaga pu depip eh erofeb stnemom elbatrofmocnu rof no deliart tI
.egdelp diputs ruoy yas ll'I ,eniF"
htaerb sih rednu delbmurg flow ehT ".wonk
ylteiuq daeh sih gnuh lerriuqs ehT ".gniht
.lla rof nuf dna ytrebil htiW"
nibac sih ni enoyreve sekaw snevetS rolesnuoC taht em dlot 3 nibac ni ekiM ,lleW"
.deraeppasid dah xof elttil eht esuaceb
,rotceriD eht ot klat ot evah d'uoy neht dna
.wonk ll'I ,tegdif neve uoy fI
.tlep sih fo spmulc yci ta llup ot lewot eht desu eh sa
,sneet etal sih ni flow a saw rolesnuoC ehT
"-sdnats pmac ruo hcihw rof cilbuper eht ot dnA"
.uoy tisybab ot gniog ton m'I .gnihton tuB" "-tuB"
,niaga srewohs eht dehcaer eh emit eht yB
.deksa elamef ehT "?nahoR ylggirW"
ffo secap derdnuh a morf mih gnicaF
,reganeet a tsomla saw ehS
woble sih ta deraeppa nahoR ".nur t'noD
.oot dnuora eb ot mih lleT" ".regoR"
.niaga dnuora decnalg xof ehT
.knurt sih ni neddih ydnac fo hsats a dah ekuL taht tuo dnuof dah snevetS rolesnuoC ,thgin tsal taht em dlot ekiM !erom s'erehT"
.hcnul erofeb thgir gnimmiws neht
,lerdnaK yb ”galF eht etulaS“
,deunitnoc ylehtilb eH
,niaga mraw saw eh emit eht yB
,nahoR .nahoR emoclew ,oS .thgiR"
.mih rentrap ot decrof saw enoemos dna
,truh seot dna sregnif siH
"!levarg eht no tooferab nur t'noD"
--tuo rehtruf eno morf esruc a dna
,pmac eht fo wal nekopsnu yB
.yawyna ti etorw yllacisab uoy os
.niaga nwod dooh sih dellup nahoR ".taht ,thgiR"
.teknalb gnizeerf a ekil dnuorg eht degguh gof dna
,etagergnoc srepmac eerht tsael ta reverehw
.dooh nwo sih kcab werht yevaD erofeb
kcilc gniyfsitas a gnikam
.thgilhsalf eht ot elgna euqilbo na ta ti dleh dna
.evod rolesnuoC eht sa
,meht noitseuq dluoc rotcerid eht erofeb ,nehT
"?nekat tog hsats s'ekuL ?tahW"
.yadot rentrap ruoy eb ll'I .enif ,yakO"
".'ylggirW' em llac t'noD"
.ecnelis neddus s'pmac eht ssorca deohce elop eht gnittih epor fo dnuos eht dna ,deknay yevaD
.dnah sih koot repmac redlo eht sa demaeb eh ,hguoht ,yadoT
,thgir pmac eht wohs d'tahT
,enoyreve ta delwocs eH
.etulas eht ni denioj neve wef a ,tibah ro etor yb rehtehW
.nirg a derahs srotaripsnoc ruof ehT ".krad
,deppots eH "-od ew od tahW
dnif dluoc yeht stnemrag ekil-ebor dna gnilaecnoc tsom eht ni dalc erew srebmem eettimmoc wollef sih
.selddap eht tuo deggard neht
.deciton dah snevetS rolesnuoC
.lwocs delffab a htiw tuoba dekool rotcerid ehT
.nwonk llew saw tepmurt ehT .dehtuom yevaD
,tenalPruF yb ygolohtnA ytirahC tserrufniaR eht ni
.dnuorg eht tsniaga dehsal liat sih dna
"?yas uoy did tahW"
.egrev hclum krab eht otni gniylf selbbep gnidnes
.gniteem trevoc eht dednuorrus taht
.nibac ot nibac gnitnuh saw flow dalc yks eht won dna ,dnuorg ot enog dah nahoR
.htap eht ta derats dna daeh sih deppord yevaD ".flesruoy
,ebor gnilaecnoc ,krad a evah t'ndid remocwen ehT ".iH"
.gnitiaw dna desufnoc doots won dna llac sih derewsna d'yehT
.devil trohs saw worros rieht tub
repmuj sih fo tekcop eht morf repap koobeton fo parcs a dellup eH
pu steg eh erofeb peels ot kcab teg yllaer nac eno on taht duol os si kcolc mrala sih zuc' nehT
"?miws t'nac I rebmemeR" "?tahW"
,thgie-ytnewt xis ta gninrom yrevE
.tnedicni elopgalf eht rof yrros ylurt si ohw
.snevetS rolesnuoC saw
,uoy llet I" "-ot del secnatsmucric tahw erac t'nod I
,gnilttar erew hteet sih
.meht nioj ylbativeni lliw erom
gninrom eht fo ruoh gniworrah eht evivrus dluoc taht sresir ylrae wef ehT
,thgir sih ot ffO ".siht
,sllup gnol ruof htiW ".tnuoc
seirots s’lerdnaK fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.drow tsal eht deohce eettimmoc derehtag ehT ".nemA" ".nemA"
".niaga ni sllaf eh fi dne peed eht morf mih evas ot evah t'nod I sa gnol sA" .deffuh ehS ".eniF"
.tluaf ym t'nsaw ti ,uoy ot raews I"
?tca t'ndluoc yeht fi ,ti fo tniop eht saw tahW
.niaga gniteem eb t'now noisserppO dnE ot eettimmoC eht ,yrroS" .yllufepoh
.snevetS rolesnuoC denroda yltnecer os dah taht
.pmac siht ta tnemyolpme deunitnoc ruoy ssucsid ot deen ew taht ,snevetS .rM ,eveileb I .hguonE"
.tseuqer eht detaeper eh ,hteet dettirg neewteb morF
yduolc saw gninrom ehT
.ti enod dah nahoR ,ylggirW toN
tekcaj efil egnaro-ytefas eht
.ecnatsid eht morf pu detaolf eciov degarne s'rolesnuoc eht
ecafrus ykrum eht htaeneb deraeppasid neht
.dereffo neeb d'ti ecno hcnarb evilo eht esufer ot tuoba t'nsaw eH
.etaidemmi saw esnopser ehT ".egdelp
,tol elohw eht detacsifnoc snevetS taht dias ekiM"
.snevetS fo esuaceb etibtsorf tog srepmac eht fo eno fi
srepmac derdnuh ruof tsomla fo staorht yhctarcs dna yrd eht morf nwad eht dedlareh
,esuohtaob eht fo edahs eht ni dennuts doots yevaD elihw ,nehT
,thgis fo tuo rolesnuoc eht htiW ".derewohs
spmulc ni nedrah ot trats ruf pmad sih leef ydaerla dluoc yevaD ".emit
,nibac sih ot egdurt ot nageb dna denrut eH ".snevetS
,ezag dloc 'snevetS rednu
,ydeer dna mils saw eciov s'regoR "?ot evah I oD"
,ecafrus eht no debbob eh sa deirc dna delgrug nahoR
.flesreh rolesnuoc a eb ot hguone dlo tsomla saw ohw rebmem ylno rieht saw aramaT .deldeehw yevaD ".tuo su pleh ot stnaw eh ,aramaT ,no emoC"
.egdelp eht dehsinif regoR ".lla
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,mraw saw tserof eht
.derewohs tsuj I ,prewt nmaD"
.sregnif yci 'snevetS rolesnuoC ni depsalc
.ezag s'rolesnuoc eht rednu detliw yevaD ,ffo derepmacs
.yawa klaw dna siht ekaT
.raews ot desoppus t'nerew slrig taht dlot neeb d'ehS
).erauqs ,yletarucca erom ,ro(
,snevetS rolesnuoC daerd eht yb dettimmoc seiticorta fo swen uoy htiw gnirb uoy
.dnim sih ni revo noitasrevnoc eht gninnur
.tlep sih ni mrof ot detrats slatsyrc eci erofeb
,retaw eht otni kcab detlit eh sa ecnatsiser on evag nahoR
,pu depip rebmem driht A ".yawyna
dooh reh derewol yllanif aramaT ".ylggirW
.noisserppo htiw pu tup tub tuoba klat ot eettimmoc eht t'nsaw tI
.eromyna egdelp eht kaeps ot tnaw t'nod I"
.erofeb ekuL ekil srepmac morf ydnac thguob lla d'yehT
"...rrrE ...eht thguat eb ll'uoY" .ecnelis elbatrofmocnu gniworg eht otni deppets yevaD ".nahoR
.yawa detnirps dna delley xof elttil eht
.tcnasorcas erew sehsats esohT
?thgir ,ylwols yawa klaW
hctal eht dekoohnu yevaD
.sretsgnuoy deye yraelb fo selggarcs dna spmulc ni dewollof
,noisserppO dnE ot eettimmoC eht fo srebmem eht ,eW"
.draobrevo rentrap sih polf ot dnah eno desu neht
sknurt miws neerg ylgniltrats eht erew sdnah sih nI
.ylnmelos denotni yevaD ".egdelp
.niaga ti od dna kcab og dias I
,regna fo ksam digir a ecaf sih htiw nevE
,ylraelc deirrac gnituohs ehT
,tfos saw eciov s'rolesnuoc ehT ".won
.lla rof nuf dna ytrebil htiw ,sdnats pmac ruo hcihw rof cilbuper eht ot dnA
dah tahW !pu tes neeb d'eH
.ot desoppus saw eh erofeb setunim owt elohw a
.yevaD ,gninrom yreve gninnur uoy nees ev'I .hguone doog toN"
.deraeppasid dah xof eht erehw morf teef wef a tsuj sehsalps deiznerf htiw detpure retaw eht ,sdnoces nihtiW
.sknurt neerg eht tnew ecalp sti nI
nibac mraw eht otni kcab ti ekam ot delggurts eh sa
.seitivitca rieht ot kcab enoyreve ,no emoC" .eciwt sdnah reh deppalc ehS
smehtna ylthgin rieht gnas krad eht fo serutaerc suoirav eht ,meht dnuorA
.tey ylreporp kcat ot thguat neeb t'ndah yehT
.deggurhs neht ,desuap yevaD ".pleh
.ecnatsid eht morf stna fo gnirettacs eht ekil demees
.remmus rieht fo tser eht sdrawot ffo derepmacs dna yawa denrut yeht
.redluohs sih revo gnuls lewot a htiw esuoh-taob eht otni deppets rolesnuoC eht
taoblias )repmac-owt ro( nam-eno elttil rieht koot yeht sa
.taht ta deddon yehT ".knurt
.elopgalf eht fo ffo stnap esoht ekat enoemos dnA"
.htap sih decarter eh
"-mih eucser og ot dah rolesnuoc eht dna ,snossel gnilias gnirud ekal eht otni llaf eh t'ndiD" .xof eht ta ylithguah deralg terref erutam erom a dna
noisserppO dnE ot eettimmoC eht fo gniteem siht llac I neht ,thgiR"
,egar neddih a deksam ti tub
".miws t'nac I tluaf ym toN"
,ylduol oot tib a derepsihw neht
desrepsid dworc ehT ".yratinasnu s'tI
.mih rof dehsinif aramaT ".noisserppo
,tuh stfarc dna stra eht sdrawot ffO
,flesti pmac eht saw ehS
,ti dne ot detnaw yeht fI
.enil eht morf ti dehcated dna galf eht derewol yevaD
.thgis eht deretsiger seye sih erofeb eciwt knilb ot dah yevaD
"?gnilias od uoy tel llits yehT"
,rotceriD eht saw ehS
deltsirb liat s'xof ehT
.srepmac delbmessa ylsuoenatnops eht morf sgnirettum ytliug erew erehT ".seitivitca
.niaga levarg eht no tooferab gninnur uoy hctac em tel t'noD .thgiR"
.ylggirW dekcip yllanoitnetni eh sa selggig dna seralg eht dootshtiw eh
.nahoR ,draeh uoy tahw yas tsuJ" ".did I thguoht I"
"?taht yas uoy t'ndid yhw nehT" ".od I naem I"
.ma'am ,srepmac eht saw tI"
.niaga ecnelis saw erehT
,mih ot txen enipluv gnirevihs eht sa dellihc sa tsomlA
,nibac eht otni flesmih werht yevaD ".niaga
,ytivitca txen rieht ot rettacs ot nageb srepmac eht fo tser eht elihw dna
.pleh t'nod uoy fi krow t'now ti tub ,aedi na tog ev'I"
,wed eht ni ylthgils gnimaets daeh sih htiW
.kcod eht rof gnikam saw yevaD emit eht yb taob nwo sih dedraob-er ydaerla dah rolesnuoc ehT
.taht degnarraer yllatnem yevaD ,oN !ti enod dah ylggirW ,haH .seert eht neewteb morf ruf yarg dna der fo sehsalf ees ylno dluoc yevaD
.tnereffid on saw yadot os
"!yawa skeew owt elohw a s'tahT"
.yltnangidni deirc xof ehT ".ot
.ylggirW s'ti tuB"
,denotni regoR ,tnemom eht gnipsarg ylnedduS
.yrots sih nageb eh
"-tuo dloc s'ti tuB"
.hsalps gnidnuoser a htiw
enituor lamron sih htiw llew tis t'ndid ynahpipe eht dna
.esuohtaob eht fo tuo detekcor snevetS rolesnuoC ,mih dniheB
".nibac ym ot kcab gniog m'I ,ylsuoires siht ekat ot gniog t'nera syug uoy fi ,kooL"
si yrots s’yadot dna
.ezag s'xof ynwarcs eht dewollof dna denaorg yevaD .ylevitruf tuoba
ma ytriht evif ta
.deppiy xof ehT "!oN"
.aramaT dna regoR erew etispmac eht fo retnec eht nI
.tceffe rof dedda nahoR
.siht rof rotcerid eht ot gnikaeps eb ot gniog er'uoY
,sroloc gnihsalc fo noissecorp yeltom a nI
.netsil ot denrut srae lla dna
galF eht etulaS:yojne esaelP
.sedis sih ot dehcnelc erew stsif sih dna
.moc.enilnoyxof.www no
,yevaD dna nahoR saw ti
!ytriht evif ,haeY"
.lufesu reh edam taht dna
,eneres saw retaw eht ereh tuO
.gnikool t'nerew yeht nehw strihs rieht fo skcab eht nwod dna
ecnats sih ni ylduorp nettirw saw ytiroirepus sih dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.htaerb fo tuo dna gnitnap llits
.diputs llits s'tI ?oS"
"?ereh gniod lla uoy era tahW"
"!rehtie ,detpurretni eb ton lliw I dnA" "-fo tol taht dna
.ylleb sih tsniaga ograc suoicerp sih edih ot gniyrt
.emeht larolf a htiw eidooh deid-eit a htiw eud edam eh os
elopgalf eht morf kcab deppets yevaD ".eciffo
.lortnoc koot ylkciuq rolesnuoc eht ,erohs no kcaB
.yracs saw ehs dna
.egdelp eht kaeps won lliw regoR"
,won eettimmoC eht fo trap saw triuqs elttil eht ,eruS
,pmac eht fo retnec eht sdrawot denrut ylbmun yevaD
sknurt miws neerg thgirb gnitrops ydob hsiyerg a
.snevetS rolesnuoC eliv eht fo sehctulc eht morf
sdaeh rieht no sdrazil dna sgorf fo
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,staob ybraen morf spsag erew erehT
snezined tserof eht revo draeh eb ot hguone duol ylerab
,pets yreve gnicart eye s'rolesnuoc eht htiW
.nalp s'enoemos wollof ot deen yllautneve d'yeht
.dloc eht ni gnirettahc morf waj sih peek t'ndluoc eh
,hguoht ,etib tsal eht detalucitsam ylwols eh sA
"-emA" ,egdelp eht dehsinif dna shtuom rieht denepo eettimmoc eht fo srebmem ruof eht ,eno sA
,tseliv sih gnikool ydaerla dna desserd ylluf saw eH .eritta sih dna
,elbuort ni uoy tog snalP
.ylsuovren tuoba gnikool ,detliw regoR
,renoohcs s'yevaD otno pu kcab delleporp saw nahoR gnilialf eht ,stnemom nihtiW
.enirtal eht ot kcab depmort yevaD
.snibac dnaldoow ytekcir ytnewt otni dekcap
.tnemom a rof derettuts xof ehT "...hu ,I" "?ton uoy od
.yltpurba ffo tuc eciov siH "-yehT
.srevihs sih fo ecrof eht htiw gnikahs saw ydob eritne sih
.etibtsorf ot esolc neeb d'eh taht naem tsum taht dna
...reven I lleW !snevetS .rM"
elcric eht dnuora sdon erew erehT .denotni yevaD ".deed
,ekops yevaD sa denworf eerht rehto ehT ".niaga
,hguoht ,yako s'tahT
.lerriuqs eht ta noitatirri ni delwocs elzzum enilef ,ynwat A
.iH" .deunitnoc yevaD ".nahoR
.edarit eht ot denetsil eh sa elims sih edih t'ndluoc regoR
,ecafrus ekal dicalp eht revo deirrac eciov siH ".won
.srae rieht ot cisum ekil detfird lasufer dekcinap snevetS rolesnuoC ".tluaf
.drawrof deppets srepmac rehto eht fo enO ".ylimE"
,yldetraeh-flah delbmurg nahoR ".ereh
.reH ot klat ot detnaw srepmac eht fo enon dna
.flesruoy truh ot gniyrt yllanoitnetni era sdik uoy raews I"
.snevetS on tub ,dnuora srolesnuoc erew erehT
"?yadot gnilias ni rentrap ym eb oS" "?oS .haeY"
.flesmih dlot yevaD
.tnuoc eno siht ekam dnA .regoR ,won thgiR"
.psarg sih otni gnihtemos devohs dna