.uoy htiw eb ot drah os t’nsaw ti hsiw I
derudne evah ohw ereh srehto era ereht taht dna
retlehs elttil taht ni kcaB
yhw etartsulli ot si yrots sihT
,nwod srae ruoy htiw das uoy gniees etah I
,og ot emit saw ti yas t’ndid eW .uoy
”eM sa emaS“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
slaed yrots sihT
.elpoep reeuq tsniaga dna
,yltnelis yrc ylno nac I tub
,etisbew sih ot sknil hcihw ,eeffoc.eyethgin
.sub eht no staes dnif dna
,yrarbil eht dniheb tuo ,yadretsey niar eht nI
.sevlesmeht morf tnereffid oot si taht
si uoy tuoba gnihtyrevE
,ew era tcefrepmi os
,taes eht tsniaga selttes liat
,od meht fo ynam oot raf
.su etah yeht nosaer emas eht s’taht tey
.dlrow siht ni ecaps hcum pu gnikat er’ew ekil
.gnipoord liat
,spihsnoitaler xes emas tsniaga yrtogib ,aibohpomoh htiw
gnirpsyaD seyEthgiN yb ”.eM sa emaS“   -eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ydaer erew uoy em dlot seye ruoy depiw uoy sa don das ,tfos ruoy
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
.em tsniaga tuo hsal semitemos yeht nosaer eht s’ti wonk I
ton s’tI .erac yeht yhw dnatsrednu t’nod I
.krad eht ni gnikrul llits srehto ,gnidih srehto
,ti ekat dna dnah ruoy rof hcaer I
.etah dna nrocs htiw netfo oot raf tem si evol ruo ,rehtegot efil a dliub ot gnikees srevol gnuoy owt sa ,elpoep sa su gniees fo daetsnI
;stekcit eht teg ot detnaw
.truoC eht ni etoyoC ruoy
,refas erehwemos ot tekcit sub
uoy fi ksa ot dedeen ylno I
,noitcennoc siht sevird taht emas eht er’ew tcaf eht s’tI
,su ekil wef os era ereht ekil sleef tI
.srae ruo nopu nwod gnihsarc emac lla ti erofeb rehtegot lleh siht fo tuo klaw dluoc ew
,enola ton era uoy taht rebmemer esaelP
a gnihctulc ,yadot uoy ot txen ereh gnidnats m’I sa dna
ruoy sA .ecaep ni uoy evol ot tnaw tsuj I .gnoleb I erehwemos retlehs dnif ot tnaw tsuj I
recnaD nedloG eht fo sracS dellac levon yrruf citore na dehsilbup yltnecer eH
.kcab hsup dluoc ew rehtegot tub
.eb dluohs ew yas yeht tahw tsniaga os
taht gnola hguone raf teg ot deganam ew taht
,su sa evarb sa eb reven lliw meht fo emos wonk I
,ozirraC yb uoy rof daer
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knaht dna ,edirP yppaH
uoy sa selzzum ruo morf sehcni gnillaf niar eht
,uoy ot od yeht tahw em ta sraet tI
,em tsniaga deirc uoy sa uoy dleh I
dnuof eb nac mih dnif ot erehw dna krow sih tuoba noitamrofnI
eeffoc rof tnahcnep a evah ot deromur si ohw
.rehto hcae gniees tpek ew
,su htiw dnats ot seilla deen eW
,emas eht era eW
,desolc seye ruoy htiw hgis uoy dna
.niaga meht ecaf noos tsum ew raef su fo ynam ,snoitan ynam ni
,seye ytsim hguorhT
.emas eht od uoy ees nac I
.gnoleb ot rehto ooT
,nwot wen a ni sevlesruo rof efil wen elohw a dliub ot deen ew ydaerla dna stluda ylerab era eW
uoy esuaceb uoy evig yeht esuba eht
.yrassecen sniamer dna
,tniop siht ot ti edam ew ykcul leef dluohs ew sseug I
.evol ruo fo htped eurt
.enilefil a otno dloh dluow uoy yaw eht enim pirg sregnif ruoy gnileef
,ozziraC yb uoy rof daeR
,drawrof klaw ew sa ,repsihw uoy
.rehtegot dnats lla dluoc ew os drawrof emoc d’yeht hsiw I
,yawrood ecivres eht ni deldduh eW .gnibbos
eht gniwonk htiw
”,swodahs eht ni yats nac yeht
,tfilpu taht ,epoh evig taht ,reehc taht seirots uoy gnirb ot sevirts goD fo ecioV eht elihW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
sdrow ruoy fo dnuos eht ot gnilc I
,edisni era uoy ohw tuoba erac t’ndluohs elpoeP
,kcab kool ot tnaw I ,yawa sllup sub eht sA
,emas eht gnieb rof nur ot dah ohw elpuoc ylno eht t’nerew ew hsiw I
,emoh remrof ym ta kool ot tnaw I
,yldaS .evol uoy ohw
tey dna ,flow ym ,tcefrep
rekamelbuort nwonk a si ohw
.esuac eht m’I taht struh tI .em ekil era
uoy dnoyeb tsurt I nwot siht ni ereh enon era ereht tey
.yats ot taerg oot si etah eht tub
”,eb reve nac I sa ydaer sA“ .snepo rood
,em devol uoy em dlot
,emos rof tey
trofmoc ot dluoc I gnihtyreve did I ,mrots eht morf yawa
.segap eht ot sgnilc lanruoj ym ni kni eht sa
,ecitsujni eht tuoba yrc ot tnaw I
.efas eb ot deen ew tub
,yako s’tI“ ,em llet uoY
detfilpu eb ot deen ew tahw dna
,srehto era ereht wonk I tey dna
.su rof erutuf eht tuoba yrrow I
.seirellag dna ,seliforp aidem laicos
.taht dnoyeb m’I tub ,em nevig ev’yeht niap eht tuoba maercs ot tnaw I
,ecalp desruc siht morf yawa raf erehwemos
fi uoy truh ot gninetaerht erew stnerap ruoy taht em dlot
.su ot tsol emoh fo ytefas eht
cirotehr lacitilop cibohpsnart dna cibohpomoh ylgnikcohs ni esir eht htiw dna ,tsap nwo ruo ni siht ekil senecs decaf evah ediserif eht ta ereh su fo ynaM .morf
.enola siht eb ot thgir leef t’nseod ti tub
.gniggaw liat ,hgual uoy nehw elkraps seye lufituaeb ruoY
,gnirpsyaD seyEthgiN yb ”eM sa emaS“ saw sihT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
saw htnoM edirP
.ecaf ym gniniats sraet
.sniar ti emit txen eht retlehs dnif ll’ew woh yrrow I
.saw ti wenk htob ew tub
,em devol yeht em dlot llits stnerap ym hsiw I
eht dna pu sllup sub eht sa
.detnioppasid tca dna won em ta sdaeh rieht ekahs ylno yeht tub
,detfilpu eb ot deen ew yhw yltsenoh dnatsrednu ot tnatropmi si ti
.bmilc ot seldruh ynam os t’nerew ereht hsiw I
.snoitazilivic tneicna ,daed ni tseretni na dna
,uoy ksa I ”?ydaer uoy erA“
,nur ot tnaw t’nod I
.skroW yttoNK dellac seirots tluda fo noitcelloc na dna
.eyethgin gnitisiv yb
.truoC eht ni etoyoC ruoy