ecnad a evah s’tel tuB
.tseW eht fo tuo depollag ravomaS dlob O  ”!yag er’ew taht tcaf eht si lla ti fo hturt ehT
eno
.deb sih ot emoh gnirb thgim eh mohw gnikniht saw eH
,orevO ovitlA yb nettirw meop A
,tseW eht otni depollag ravomaS dlob O  .ravomaS dellac
,edir lacisum siht fo elyts eht tuo llif oT .edisni nwod dekcut erew reppit a dna etulf A  .edih ni derevoc dna dehsilop dna detniap llA ,edis sih yb depparts sawt‘ ,deirrac eh nrhdob A
.dab eb ot nwonk saw repmet s’ravomaS dnA
.ylyls deddon maS tuB
maS warb yb dnats oT
eno sa rehtegot denioj
,ronaelE ot detuohs maS
ni denioj snaicisum eroM
.wob a htiw demialcorp eh
.eeGcM gnuoy dlob ot egairram dna
eniw der tseteews eht htiw puc a dellif eeGcM oS
.og did ti enut eht ylirrem dna ni denioj yehT
etam a ot deerga dah deicnaf eh yllif eht roF  .etal oot tub
.enil taht ssorc ton ll’I“ dias ,dnuorg eht ot ti werht eh nehT
”,dam ton m’I eralced I“
.dah eh snopaew on tub ,tah sih dehsiruolf caM
.das m’I dna ,timda I
eelg reh gnirahs elihw reh ediseb doots caM woN
elpuoc a sa dessik nehT
.elims gib a derahs dna
.nus eht sa thgirb dna
”.won tsuj su neewteb emoc
nageb gidnihs a dna
.enihsa lla seye sih htiw maS ot ti evag dnA
,ttocS retlaW riS ot seigolopa on htiw
raB dna erutsaP s’ybrehteN dlo fO
.elihw a rof tsael ta ,uoy nioj retteb d’I“
erew yeht yppah oS
.wonk uoy gnireehc dna gnicnad erew noos dreh ehT
.ees ot noos depoh yeht ytrap dna gniddew eht tA
,sysateM yb ,yrarbiL ehT
elihw a rof denrut dna
,gnilwarb tA tseb
edirb eht ronoh ot rof
puc a em evig tsuJ
.daeh sih deddon dna
roolf dnarg eht dnuora gnuws moorg eht dna edirb ehT
”.won ssenippah ruoy oT tsaot a reffo ll’I dna
.nar yeht etag tnorf eht ot ,maS dna cirdeC elihW
,tlit lluf ta daor eht nwod defooh yehT
.etarbelec ot won detcepxe slaitpun eht dnA
rekcin thgil a evag maS
emosdnah saw cirdeC gnuoY
.tsaob sih saw taht rO
,tloc gnuoy ylevil a ,rehtorb s’ronaelE nehT
;ssarg eht sa neerg sawt‘ dna
”,elddif ym teg tsuj ll’I“ diaS
,yadot tuo dnuof ev’uoY“
gniyaS ,elims a gnikcarc
,epoh I ,sgnileef drah oN“
,dreh derehtag eht dnuor dekool eH
.dnab eht htiw dniheb morf kcohs fo seirc emac nehW dnah ni dnah
;eniw eht kcab dessot dna
”.edis reh yb sdnats won ohw noinapmoc efil evarb reh dnA
.yah dna srewolf dima doots ronaelE riaF  ”.yad a rof tsuj
.thgir taht ekam ot edosipe sunob laiceps a s'ereh oS
wob dna elddif sih htiw denruter cirdeC gnuoY
.erob yeht yrrow eht dna serac eht gnittegroF
,gnilims ,mih retfa dekool maS
sredluohs rieht re’o dehgual htoB
,now evah uoY“ ,demialcorp eH
tnemirrem eht ni nioj dnA yats ll’I gnitruoc eht ni tuo tsol ev’I hguoht roF
sdneirf reh nO thgirf dna
eltsihw sih tuo dellup eH
.serans dna stnemtimmoc dediova eh elihw nevE
,tah dekcoc a erow eH
tnemegagne reH ees ot rof yad taht derehtag dah ohw
”,ravomaS ,tem lleW“
eht saw deets taht ,yrtnuoc ediw eht lla hguorhT
:tseb eht saw etam sih yrtnuoc ediw eht lla nI
enut a detrats dna
etag eht ta pu dellup dna ekal eht dednuor maS
.goD fo ecioV ehT fo edosipe laiceps a ot gninetsil er'uoY
.wolga lla ecaf sih htiw
.flesti edosipe eht ni dedulcni t'nsaw yletanutrofnu hcihw ,sunob elttil a htiw dedulcnoc neeb evah dluohs
.noom eht fo thgil eht yb ni nioj thgim lla yeht tahT
dednetni reh ot yrujni esuaC thgim taht rovaf reh rof thgif yna diova oT yaw a gnikees saw ehs
,yrots s'yadretseY
,seram eht gnizoomhcs ta ,gnizoob ta
.tlob a ni ffo koot dna
,ekoj s’maS ta delims ehs sA
.ssalg ekil delkraps yeht dna laoc sa kcalb liat dna enaM