.snoissap rieht dewollof nairE
,smra dna sgel rieht hguorht devled
.sedis rieht tsniaga tfos ssarg eht ,gnitnap
ydob dranreB .tS rieht fo hcuot rednet eht leef dluoc yeht woh devol yeht dna
.citehporp saw ti tub—ekoj tsetaerg eht t’nsaw tI
.stsehc rieht ot pu swap zzaj thguorb eerht lla dna ,thgir denael cirE
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.atad daed fo seirautcnas gnilfits esoht ni ton dna
,ruf kcalb rieht otni desserp kcoc eninac rieht fo pit eht sa
,ymaerc dna ,teews ,yruovaS
,yas ot nwod nomed a dnes dluow nataS
”.seiraed ,uoy knahT
.mih hguorht cigam eht detcerid yeht nehT
.stsaerb rieht deraes dna draeb nworb rieht fo elcillof yreve dehcrocs tI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,doots dna dnuorg eht no kcab swap kcalb rieht tup yehT
.ygolohtna sliveD htiw gnicnaD eht ni deraeppa tsrif yrots sihT
.bew eht otni tuo seceip eht dehsup dna
.dedolpxe dlrow riehT
”,edurtreG teews ,hO“ .dias edurtreG
.dehgual enoyreve elihw
”.smooR gnitiaW ni ylduoL muG skcamS ohW yehT evres dna
,tilc rieht gnola eugnot enilef hguor rieht dils yehT
.ecno ta lla laerehte dna yhtrae
,elzzum reh dnuora gnilknirw niks esool reh ,delims ehS
.ylleb sih fo taf tfos eht otni knis ot ydob
,selzzum nedlog dna kcalb rieht neewteb ssik eht ekorb yehT
.ruovalf eht deruovas dna etib rehtona koot nairE .recnamoreip
.niks rieht gnilooc ria thgin eht dna
,ston od dna sod rieht htiw stelbat delesihc rieht dah slegnA
,llub ,eltrut fo sehsalF
”,krow live eht pu peeK“
,demossolb niaP .hself
sdnarts eht gnola derevihs taht tsul dna noitatcepxe eht ecart dluoc nairE ,redips a ekiL
”,hguoht ,nevoc siht toN“
.dnuorg eht no ahtagA dial dna
.daeh nworb rieht ekorts ot
.kciuq dna hguor gnimoceb gnitsurht rieht
.kcalb tnew dlrow riehT
,sdrow rof gniporg dnim rieht tlef yeht
,kcab ydob kcalb rieht dellup yehT
,flesmeht etsat dluoc yeht dna
.seye sih dellor cirE .detuop maS
.stsaerb llams rieht gnippuc dna
,maS ot dettonk llits erew yehT
shtaehs rieht morf degreme skcoc s’cirE dna maS
.bew eht otni evlossid flesmeht tel dna
.ehtaerb ot ecaps on meht evag cigam eht tub
,ereh erew yeht yhw s’tahT
.eton eht gnidloh
,meht ot pu emac eh sa nairE revo derewot trebreH
”?egairram litnu gnitiaW
ecivres ni stneduts rieht detarogivni tahw thguat ylno sredle nevE
.regnol hcum tsal ton dluow yeht wenk yehT
”,reed elttil doog a hcuS“
.tsul htiw meht ta ezag seye wolley ,tnecsenimul rieht dehctaw dna ,deleenk yehT
!did ti hsiw I ,em xeh ssenkraD fo droL“ .deksa nairE
cirE dna ,maS ,ahtagA
,peed tnew eugnot riehT
,revo dna revo kcoc rieht no nwod spih rieht demmals yehT
.swen fo tib a evah I“
.anigav tew ,nellows rieht dna ,stsaerb trep ,llams rieht
,deggaw liat rieht sa dnA .anigav rieht edisni detrad eugnot rieht sa deggaw liat riehT .meht hguorht dehsaw erusaelp fo sevaw eht sa kcab dehcra sreltna riehT .dehctaw yeht
,lluf ni egagtrom rieht diap sreppuH eht taht wohs ot krowrepap s’knab eht lla etumsnart eW“
.thgit dezeeuqs yeht sa retcnihps rieht dekar kcoc rieht fo enips yrevE .eno sa—
,hteet rieht dettirg yehT
.taorht enivrec rieht ot wap rehtnap ,kcalb rieht thguorb yeht nehT
.redluohs nworb rieht tsniaga debbur tfahs rieht dna
kcoc rieht tsniaga ti dezeeuqs yehT
.srieht lla dna tnereffid lla saw tI
,meht htaeneb yal eh dna
”,senohprae gniraew sruf ynam os ot klat ot gniog m’I“
.taorht rieht ni gniyrub kcoc rieht dna ,shtuom rieht otni repeed gnidils seugnot rieht
.anigav rieht fo tuo elzzum eninac rieht dellup yehT
,gnitirw rieht ekil uoy fI
”.noisrevnoc debhtaed eht rof llaf syawla yeht tuB“
”.hgU“ .eip reh htiw nwod gnittis ,dias ahtagA
,ecaf s’ahtagA puc edurtreG dehctaw nairE
anigav rieht fo spil eht hguorht dils eugnot egral rieht sa edisni dehsup dna retcnihps rieht tsniaga desserp eugnot hguor riehT
,sosrot rieht otni rehtruf gniggid sreltna rieht
.niaga meht detelpmoc dna emac hsalf txen eht litnu—
.deggag yeht sa deggaw
nevoc a nioj ot ydaer eb ll’ehs ,neethgie snrut ehs sa noos sA
.eip sih fo etib a koot maS
.gnitsurht peek yeht dna meht nopu si msagro wonk yeht nehw
.kcoc rieht fo daeh eht dnuora driht rieht delriws yeht sa rehto hcae tsniaga seugnot owt rieht desserp yehT
,anigav rieht otni yaw sti decrof tonk rieht sa retcnihps rieht dekar senips riehT
,eiraed ,dnA“ .dias edurtreG
doog fo secrof eht no covah kaerw ot nalp tnellecxe na saw depoh yeht tahw dah nairE .gnitartsurf saw ti ,noisacco no ,llitS
,kcoc dettonk ,gnignah rieht tsap ,srae dehcra ,llams rieht hguorht
.ekacpuc eht koot yeht sa ylleb deniats-muc ,evissam s’trebreH ta gnikool flesmeht dnuof nairE dna
stsaerb dna stilc dna sessa dna skcoc fo sehsalF
:dah cigam eht sa drah sa tsomla
.eugnot rieht no detlem selppa eht dna hteet talf rieht no dekalf tsurc eht
.trid eht otni sregnif rieht gud yeht dna ,dewolleb yeht ,dehtirw yehT
.kooc taerg a m’I“
esaelp ylniatrec tsom lliw sihT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.suoiciled saw tI
.cirE ta deralg ahtagA .detuohs cirE
.rehtegot dekcol selzzum eninac dna enilef
”,eiraed ,esruoc fO“
neesnu na ot nairE gnitcennoc
,liat kcalb ,niht rieht morf derevihs yehT
”.stsehc toh owt neewteb desserp eb annog m’I esuaceb“ ,dias yeht
ssa wolley rieht ot nwod wap enilef rieht dils yeht nehT
wap rieht otni taps yeht sa dloc dna ytpme tlef ssa rieht dna
.cimagA morf noitnetta tserw ot deganam ehS ”.nairE“
”,thginot htgnerts taht deen ll’I ,yllufepoH“
.ti htaeneb sreniatnoc owt rehtona ees dluoc nairE dna
.ylippah liat reh dehsiws edurteG
.rehtaeH elttil ruo fo duorp os er’eW“
.kcoc rieht otno anigav rieht derewol yeht elihw
.raey lufwa na dah mraf reppuH eht
.og ot ydaer saw nevoc eht dna
.ssarg eht ni depoord liat reh dna
”!eiraed ,suollevram kool yehT“
.dlrow eht ni etanracni live fo modgnik eht ekam dna
osrot ehtil s’nairE dnuora swap sih gnidils
”.elihwhtrow eb ot ti rof roop oot er’yehT“ .dias maS
.bew eht gnola selppir tnes thguoht hcae dna
.ylevol saw taht
”,niur gniredluoms a s’nevaeh erofeb syad eerht ti evig I“ ”!?nevaeh nI ?eM
.wap sih htiw ecaf ediw reh gnikorts ,dias maS
”,esaelp ,seiraed ,cimagA“ ”—inroh tnatsnoc ruoy llac uoy tahw taht sI“
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.meht revo dehsarc erusaelp sa deraor dna dessih dna detnurg dna deoom dna dekrab yehT
.drohc eht gnitelpmoc
.leef ylno dluoc yehT
.ssa rieht fo tuo gnippop eugnot rieht
,llews sirotilc rieht dna nethgit sllab rieht leef dluoc yehT .retteb eht
,eno sa seciov ytnewT
.anigav rieht otni repeed elzzum eninac rieht gnihsup
,demossolb ecips fo tnih eht sa
”.seivoM ni senecS esneT gniruD sklaT ohW yehT fo yhtroW
,ahtagA“ .dias maS dna cirE ”!oyyeH“ .derumrum ahtagA
,kcoc rieht otno flesmeht dellup yeht nehT
cigam eht detcerid yehT
.kcab nworb rieht decaf dna
deworrub ti erofeb
,eslup hcae deklim sretcnihps rieht ,anigav dna ssa ot meht deit stonk rieht ,skcoc rieht morf derif muc toH
,desilaer yeht ,ruof ,on—seciov eerht
”fo ecils a evah nac uoy fo lla neht dna noitaitini eht mrofrep ew t’nod yhW“
.erac t’ndid yehT
.elims a htiw nairE ot revo deretnuas yeht nehT
.sreltna rieht yb nwod daeh rieht dehsup
”?noitulosba rof gniyarp
gnimlehwrevo saw tI
”.stneidergni tew eht dda uoy erofeb thgir tneper ot gniog er’uoy legna eht ecnivnoc ot si kcirt ehT
,dnuorg eht no erew yeht nehT
.eriflleh ekil tlef ti dnA
.kcab s’maS dnuora swap kcalb rieht dna ,sredluohs s’cirE no swap nedlog rieht ,ssa s’cirE no sregnif suonitarek ,nworb rieht
s’nairE ”.lairt eht ta od dluoc ew gniht live tsom eht desilaer I dna
,detarapes yeht nehT
.anigav rieht fo spil eht neewteb dils kcoc dettonk rieht fo pit eht sa
tfos rieht otni tib dna ruf eht hguorht dils hteet riehT
nedrah kcoc dettonk rieht tlef yehT
,rehto hcae dnuora smra rieht depparw yehT
,skcoc rieht dniheb tliub erusserP
kcoc rieht fo daeh eht rednu gnidils eugnot s’ahtagA leef dluoc yehT
tnemom gnol ylbissopmi eno taht sa ,sredduhs sa ,selgnit sa
,eugnot yrebbols ,gnol rieht htiw tuo dehcaer yehT
elzzum nedlog gnol rieht otni
”?noitacifitoN a evaH t’noD uoY nehW enohP ruoY setarbiV ohW yehT dna live evres ot cigam siht lla esu ew llahs woh ,seiraed ,woN“ .dehguoc ehs nehT
”,tsud enob legna dnuorg-erp esu ot dah I os ,gnimoc otni legna na kcirt ot eganam t’ndluoc I“
.nworb htiw dekcelf ruf yerg eht ,deggaw liat reh dna
,gniniwtretni selzzum nworb dna kcalb rieht
.tniop eht ssim dluow ti ,KO ,dnA
,esnefed ym nI“ .dias maS
sreltna s’nairE dnuora sevlesmeht depparw cigam krad fo slirdnet elpruP  regguR .P .B yb
”?uoy nac ,tnemom ecin eno evah em tel t’nac uoY“
htgnerts gniniamer rieht lla desu yeht sa ecnalab ot ydob kcalb rieht dnuora smra wolley rieht depparw yehT
,repeed ti wolla ot kcab wolley rieht dehcra yehT
peed ni flesmeht dellup yehT
.kniht t’ndluoc nairE
.elims a otni dereviuq spil reH
.derevihs edurtreG ”,hhhhO“ .dias nairE
,demialcxe edurtreG
.rehto hcae tsniaga ylpmil detser seugnot rieht dna ,kcoc rieht dnuora kcals gniog ydaerla saw htuom rieht teY
,hctorc wolley rieht tsniaga debbur
,ssarg eht no flesmeht yal dna
.retcnihps rieht hguorht kcoc denips rieht decrof yeht nehT
.eduerfnedahcs evitcidniv
eht yb detarran si noisrev kooboidua eht dna
?enigami uoy dluoC“
.etarapes ot nairE dna mih rof hguone detalfed yllanif tonk s'maS sa sekacpuc sih tuo gnidnah
.rae rieht otni derepsihw ehs
.nairE ot rewop sti gnidnib
.meht morf yawa deppils ssensuoicsnoc tuB .drah dna denips
.gnikcilf srae rieht
.dehgual ehs sa ylleb reh derevoc smra niht s'edurtreG
.cigam eht ot dnim yrev reh deit dna
,dluoc yeht sa thgit sa dellup yehT
”,su revo nevaeh elgnad od yehT“
.noitarapes rieht yb detum swap zzaj rieht fo tceffe eht ,deirc cimagA ”!nataS dnA“
”,ti tae ot noitaitini retfa litnu tiaw ot tnaw yam uoy hguoht
,ssarg eht otni erp deppird kcoc dettonk rieht tuB
.regae syawla saw reveirter eht—
,anigav rieht fo sdlof eht neewteb
dekcub kcab s’ahtagA sa
noos tuB .anigav rieht ni peed deirub kcoc rieht leef neve t’ndluoc yeht
.taorht rieht tsniaga gnibbur senips rieht ,htuom rieht fo kcab eht hguorht dehsup kcoc rieht fo daeh ehT
”,ssa ruoy snaem eH“
tseb eht neeb syawla dah edurtreG
.tnesnoc tuoba relkcits a saw edurtreG
.stfahs rieht degassam
”,eiraed ,og uoy erehT“ .devivrus dah
”?dnik os eb uoy dluow
,elcric eht dnuora tnew trebreH
.flesmeht fo tnecs yhtrae ,peed eht ni gnihtaerb
.deksa edurtreG
.rehtegot gnireviuq seidob rieht
”?dael yeht reverehw snoissap live ruoy wollof dna yteirporp doog fo sdnuob eht morf flesruoy eerf ot ydaeR“
daeh sih no swap reh decalp ehs nehT
,doots dna dnuorg eht tsniaga swap eninac rieht dehsup yehT
detuohs yeht ”!nataS dnA“
;eip eht otni tib nairE
—”ssenisub ruo nigeb ew erofeb
selcsum reh dnuora slirdnet eht delriws yehT
ylleb evissam s’trebreH ni elzzum eninoil sih deirub eH ”!suoegrog siht gnikool ylleb s’trebreH peek ot sah enoemoS
,reniatnoc lacirdnilyc a denepo trebreH ”.sekacpuc edam I“
”?elyts htiw ti od t’nac uoy fi live gnieb fo tniop eht s’tahW“
.deifillom tahwemos ,dias trebreH
,ecno ta seidob ytnewt ni gnimoc msagro tlef yehT
,netae saw eip eht lla
.seidob nworb dna kcalb rieht dnuora deklaw neht
.eugnot hguor rieht htiw eloh rieht dekorts dna ssa wolley rieht ot elzzum kcalb rieht thguorb yehT
.live gnieb fo tniop eht ssim dluow taht taht tlef yletanitsbo nataS tuB ”.htap live eht no er’uoY“ ,tsael ta ro
.detcejretni dnabsuh s’trebreH ”!yeH“
”.elggurts a llits s’ti ,sraey ytfif retfA
,dias eh ”,yllautca
.meht dnuora knarhs ylkciuq dlrow eht ,seugnot dna kcoc dnuora gnihtaerb morf dedaehthgil ydaerlA
.wap rieht fo dap eht tsniaga gnibbur niks hguor eht
,syendik rieht hguorht deretsilb neht ylleb rieht degrogne tI
dehsiw nairE ,semitemoS
,ria thgin looc eht otni detpure dna
ruf nworb ,trohs rieht no swap kcalb rieht decalp yehT
.rehtegot detnahc yehT ”!nataS ,liaH“
.gnidnetxe swalc rieht dna ,gnislup tonk rieht
?enihw hcum ooT“ .dias nairE
.edis rehtie morf nairE tsniaga desserp cirE dna maS
,lleW“ * 	        * 	         * .demaercs yeht
.rehtegot swap reh deppalc neht ,dias ehs
denaorg nairE .dias ahtagA
”?eiraed ,uoy t’nerew ,yadot skcans latioc-tsop fo egrahc ni erew uoy ,trebreH woN“ .dias edurtreG ”,etiuq ,seY“ ”.nataS“
”,enif si dnuorg-erp ,tsud enob legna nwo ruoy dnirg t’nac uoy fI“ .dias eh
.skcoc rieht dnuora anigav dna ssa
”,drab a bor erad dluow eno oN“
,yromem eht ta delims yeht
.ruf wolley rieht tsniaga debbur
,dias ahtagA ”,yllautcA“
,sregnif rieht ni swap reh koot yehT
.tonk gniworg rieht dnuora redrah gnihsup emit hcae
.teef sih ot mih depleh nairE dna ,denaorg cirE
.srieht otni tib nairE dna
.eip fo ecils a evaH“
.daeh s’nairE fo edis eht gnittap ,dias edurtreG
.krow ot tnew dna
.swap reh gnippalc
,depsag yehT .hguor dna kcils
.dias eh ”,siht tuoba MD ruo llet ot evah ot gniog er’eW“
.dias cimagA ”,mom ,seY“
.anigav rieht ni elzzum rieht deirub dna ,ydob nworb rieht fo tnorf ni ydob nedlog rieht deleenk
.dias maS ”,yl–etul–osbA“
”?mih bor yeht elihw stidnab eht edaneres ,od annog eh s’tahW“ .deksa cirE
,yromem rieht fo tuo emac nairE emit eht yB
.retto dna ,flow ,esroh ,woc
,efiw ruoy tuo tae uoy elihw dnabsuh ruoy yb dettonk gnieb naht retteb s’gnihtyna rehtehw em deksa uoy fi
,niht dna gnol ,tew dna egral ,hguor dna trohs ,kcoc tsniaga eugnot tsniaga eugnot tub gnihton tlef yehT
liat reveirter ,yffulf riehT
.detnias neeb dah yeht hguoht sa
.elbatrofmocnu tahwemos dekool tub ,dehsulb trebreH
”?yrreJ ,txen s’tahW“
”.og ot tnaw tsomla I woN“
”?retteb od lliw drab ruoy dna ,hO“
ahtagA desilaer yeht erofeb nairE drawot spets wef a koot yehT
.keew siht yadhtrib htneethgie s’rehtaeH s’tI
;tnemom a rof gnihtyreve demlehwrevo niap ehT
.siht derongi edurtreG
,epyt s’nairE t’nsaw trebreH hguohT
.eniuneg yltsom saw ti dna ,delims edurtreG .ahtagA dias
sredluohs rieht tsniaga ti debbur dna
sgel nedlog rieht revo deleenk yehT
.redrO dna dooG fo secrof eht no covah kaerw ot elba eb ll’ew ,siht htiW“
,ria rof depsag yehT .sgnul dna ,revil
.hself eno erew yeht hguoht sa ahtagA otni dna
”!seiraed ,detrats teg s’tel ,woN“
.edurtreG ediseb sreniatnoc eht ot delwarc neht
”.fehc niht a tsurt reveN“ .dias nairE
,ruomuh fo esnes tneced a kcal dna stoidi eb yam yehT .sseug I“
eson s’nairE tih llems ehT
,enoyreve ees dluoc yeht woh devol yehT
trapa gnimoc seidob rieht
.hself rieht hguorht denrub cigam live ehT
yltnelis gnitnap yal ahtagA
”,ti kroc ot deen ll’ew sseuG
.taeh sti ni dellever dna
,dias edurtreG ”,hhhhO“
,emac hsalf hcae sA
.seiraed ,uoy fo lla fo duorp m’I
”.su nioj dluoc uoy dalg os m’I
eugnot dnuora depley elzzum riehT
,etalfni ot eunitnoc tonk rieht leef dluoc yeht
elzzum wolley ,gnol rieht dessik elzzum kcalb ,trohs riehT
,gnireviuq tilc rieht ,seidob rieht hguorht srevihs tnes eugnot rieht fo kcilf yrevE
.sehsalf ni emac ti esnetni os saw tI
deppalc enoyrevE
wols neve t’ndid cigam krad eht tuB
.ssenkrad eht ni etteuohlis erem a saw rehtnap eht cirE ,elddim eht nI
.eugnot niht gnol rieht tsniaga gnibbur eugnot hguor trohs rieht ,ssik a rof
,flesmeht evoba dessik yeht sa seilleb rieht otni desserp sreltna riehT
”.staeS telioT cilbuP no enirU sevaeL ohW yehT gnivres fo yaw nwo ruo evah lla ew ,seiraed woN“ .rorroh-kcom ni deredduhs cimagA
eninoil ,delcsum rieht rof tlef ti doog woh derebmemer nairE
.meht ni repeed eugnot rieht detnaw yeht tuB
,deunitnoc nairE ”,worromoT“
”eiraeD ,nataS“ saw sihT
,sreltna rieht depsarg wap enilef ,kcalb rieht dna ,tuo mra rieht delliw yehT
,doolb rieht otni depees dna
,oga emit emos meht fo tuo deppils dah kcoc s’cirE
.detpurretni edurtreG
.kcab rieht otno despalloc tub
,dniheb morf kcen rieht dessik maS
,sdlrow eht lla ni sehctiw eht lla fO
.nuf rof ton saw siht tuB
.tsud enob legna dellik-ylhserf fo esod yhtlaeh a dna ,eciuj nomel fo hsad a ,gemtun fo hcnip A“ .dias ehs
,dias oppih gib eht ”,seY“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
nwod cirE dial nairE ,elihwnaeM
”?yadot cirE dna maS tnaw uoy oD“
.ssa rieht fo kcarc eht dna anigav s’nairE fo spil eht tsniaga desserp dna
,ssenkrad eht otni ffo gnirehtils
sthguoht reh dnuora slirdnet eht depparw nairE .niarb reh otni neht ,sgel dna
”.mih fo erac gnikat erew yeht esuaceb tsevrah eht dessim dna
.detcejretni cirE
,rebmit wol a ni tuo gnas eciov a ”,olleH“
.ssenteews fo hcuot a htiw ksum dna taews fo stnih
swalc enilef prahs rieht elihw
.devirra ohw sehctiw rehto eht etaitini ot ffo tnew dna seip rieht dehsinif dah cimagA ,nooS
erutcarf dnim rieht tlef yehT
.srieht ylbatupsidni tey
.]”!em s’tahT !yeH“ ro ”detarrevo s’eh kniht I“ ,ekil gnihtemoS .ereh ekoj a ekam ot eerf leef[ ikahK elbidercni
,mraf rieht no esolcerof ot egduj eht erofeb gniog si knab ehT“
retcnihps dna anigav rieht elihw delgnit skcoc rieht fo daeh ehT
.meht denioj ton dah
.ssa rieht htiw elzzum eninac rieht derehtoms yeht ,tauqs kciuq a htiW
.kcoc debrab rieht gnikorts nageb dna
niks rieht hguorht knas cigam ehT .enob
.sreltna rieht ot yaw eht lla dna
,seiraed ,woN“ .doots edurtreG
,dnuora dessap erew sekacpuc eht
:tac a ekil dnim s’reed eht deklats slirdnet elprup ehT
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
,retcnihps rieht hguorht dils yehT
,lortnoc dna ssensselpleh fo ,tseuqnoc dna
.taorht nworb rieht ezeeuqs ot
.devirra dah cimagA fo strap eerht ehT .denaorg nairE
wap nedlog rieht tuo dehcaer yeht dna
.ssa rieht fo ksum yhtrae eht gnitsat
,ydob rieht hguorht gnisruoc cigam fo slirdnet elprup eht tlef yehT
,eM ?seiraed ,enigami uoy dluoC“ .dehgual ehS
.eciov s’cirE ni dias yeht ”,reed elttil ,krow ot og ot emiT“
.sevlesmeht dnuora deklaw neht
.pirg rieht ni gnihsiuqs oppih a fo yllebrednu tfos eht dna ,sregnif rieht htaeneb sba eninoil drah
,efil saw derettam tahW
”,eiraed ,eip elppa fo ecils a evaH“
lluks s’nairE otni peed
.ruf emas eht htiw neve ton
.ssa rieht detnaw yehT .koohs ssa rieht
sevooh dna sdnah suonitarek rieht hguorht gud neht
,erofeb erew yeht sa dezinorhcnys sa ylraen ton ,delbmurg cimagA ”,roF“
,tsul rieht hsaelnu ot deraperp yeht sa denruter ylwols htgnerts riehT
,pu tis ot deirt nairE
,dekrep srae s’maS ”.eip ym“—
”.eiraed ,nataS gnivres fo trap lla s’ti tuB“
eciuj teews htiw htuom rieht dellif tI
.gnipsag meht gnivael
”.hcuot eltneg s’namow a tnaw I ,keew lla em ta yawa dnuop nem owt gnivah retfa“
.dias eh ”,gnici maercrettub tunaep htiw deppot dna lemarac htiw dellif sekacpuc etalocohC“
ediw gninepo elzzum tar rieht
,seye enilef hguorhT
,ssa rieht did ti sa selzzum rieht deretne seugnot riehT
.ti otni hteet eninac rieht knas dna dniheb morf sredluohs gnipols rieht was yehT
.elbatupsidni erew stluser eht dna
”!ytrap eht tilps uoY“
.nataS fo ecivres ni lla ,erised dna ,evol
.elbidercni si sihT“
”,ininap a em llaC“
.gniraelc eht fo thgilnoom mid eht otni edorts
.redluohs eht no mih dettap yehT
.sdnah rieht ni swap sih koot dna
.ssa rieht tsniaga kcab denael yeht nehT
,elcsum fo gnir eht hguorht eugnot rieht devohs yehT
”.rethguad live yllufrednow a hcus gnisiar no cimagA etalutargnoc lla s’tel oS
.dluoc yeht yaw tseb eht noisnet eht kaerb ot dediced yeht dna
”!derehtag ew cigam krad fo tnuoma lufrednow a tahw dnA“ .gnitnap
,sdnabsuh owt reh revo derewot
elzzum eninac rieht devohs dna daeh wolley rieht fo kcab eht debbarg wap enilef riehT
sevooh dna swap dna spih dna kcoc dna anigav sa trid eht otni gud sregnif suonitarek riehT .odlid a ekil ti gnisu ,anigav rieht otni
”?derentrap rufyreve sI“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,regguR .P .B yb
.ti otni deraeppasid elzzum rieht sa meht gnihsurc thgiew sti derebmemer yehT
erehwyreve ssendoog ot dne na tuoba gnirb pleh dluow lautir sihT
,nairE tsniaga ydob sih desserp cirE
,edurtreG“ .delims ehS
.ssa rieht otni redrah eht lla tsurht neht
”.nomed a yb tuo tihs neht enitneprut htiw rednelb a ni tup neeb s’taht rebbur ekil sleef daeh yM“
”.epor ym fo dne eht ta m’I esuaceB“ .dias ahtagA ”,renroc a ni flesruoy deit ev’uoy neht ,lleW“ ”.ton si ereht“—
,rehtegot enoyreve dnuob slirdnet elprup ehT
.dewob dna doots maS elihw
.eslup cigam eht leef dluoc nairE
ti sa tilc rieht ni gnitserc dna seidob rieht hguorht gnillor erusaelp rieht
,driht a gnas ”olleH“
,talf tsniaga talf dna prahs tsniaga prahs
.ahtagA ot revo deklaw nairE
.deirc cirE dna maS ”!nairE nugtohS“ ”!pu puorg ot emit s’tI“ .dias edurtreG ”,seiraed ,lleW“ .ydob rieht otni dna
.cirE dna maS ot denrut neht
tnorf ni enohs taoc nedlog s’maS
,seip reh otni evol hcum os deruop edurteG
.taht xif dluoc yehT
.skooB yrarbiL ni segaP fo renroC eht sdloF ohW yehT fo
?nigeb s’rehtona dna dne serised rieht did erehW .rehtegot demsaps
.enaL gnissaP eht ni timiL deepS eht rednu lleW sevirD ohW yehT
.elzzum eninac rieht dehctarcs
,elgae ,xof ,reed ,tar ,rehtnap ,noil ,god ,oppih
.gniraelc krad eht otni slirdnet elprup eht tnes yeht dna
.dekcoc sdaeh rieht ,reh ot denrut yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta
.erew yeht live woh tsuj sreppuH etanutrofnu eht wohs ot deticxe ,deddon enoyrevE
.seiraed ,suollevram ylpmis ,suollevram ,hO“
”eiraeD ,nataS“   :yojne esaelP
desaeler neeb tsuj sah
”.ytreporp rieht no mialc on sah knab eht dna
.fles rehtnap rieht drawot denael yeht sa
”.pirt-nac eh esuaceb ecaf sih no talf llaf annog si kcolraw ruoy“
.swap zzaj rieht od dluoc cimagA erofeb dias nairE ”,od I“
.rehtegot swap reh deppalc edurtreG
.ynomrah ni ,eciov rehtona gnas ”,olleH“
.ti gnola swalc rieht dekar dna
,mU“ .dewollaws yrreJ
.meht dedivorp dna
,dias dna ,nairE tsniaga flesmih deidaets cirE
,emas eht reven saw tI
ylleb s’ahtagA hguorht
,kcoc rieht no rewol knas yehT
.nevoc eritne eht gnitcennoc bew eht fo sthguoht gnitfihs eht tub
.klawediS elohW eht pu gnikaT elihW
.redluohs dna selzzum rieht tsniaga depsag yeht dna
.sreddu dna skaeb dna seugnot dna spih dna
neeb ton dah dnabsuh tsrif reH
.reh ot slirdnet eht dnib ot ti desu dna
elzzum wolley rieht edisni detrad eugnot hguor ,trohs riehT
tilc nellows rieht yllanif litnu thgit sivlep rieht gnizeeuqs
?yranoissiM“ .deksa maS
stonk maS nehw tilc ym no nwod etib t’ndluohs uoy ebyam neht ,ytrap eht tilps ot em tnaw t’nod uoy fI“
,gniyonna saw gninwolc sseltneler s’cimagA .devaw dna delims nairE
,dias maS ”,nairabrab s’ahtagA tuohtiW“
,sivlep rieht dehcnelc yehT .anigav rieht fo tuo dna ni gnippop
etalfni tonk rieht tlef yehT
.selzzum eerht morf denaom yeht dna
.rewop dna raef fo
dnuof ehs woh s’taht—
,tserof krad eht ni deirrac eciov niht s’edurtreG
yehT ot noitoved rieht fo ecneirepxe dnah-tsrif dah nairE tub
.stcaratac yb deduolc eulb eht ,seye s’dranreB .tS dlo dnik eht otni dekool yehT
,seye rieht denepo nairE
wap enilef riehT
.ssarg eht ni yal ti sa gnilgnit ydob elohw rieht dna gnislup kcoc denips rieht
.ssenkrad eht ni tser eht nioj ot tuo slirdnet eht tnes dna
.erom detnaw yeht dna
,levon tsrif rieht
.edurtreG dias
,ahtagA desuffus yletelpmoc dah cigam eht ,yllaniF
.sselepoh saw ti wenk yeht hguoht neve ,yawa cigam eht delliw yletarepsed nairE
,htuom rieht ni llits saw kcoc rieht fo pit ehT
cigam krad eht ot cirE gnidnib dehsinif nairE
ecrof hguone htiw rehto hcae depmub-tsehc yeht sa detuohs cirE dna maS ”!srewop obmiH“
,tfel denael maS nehT .dias
,dessap setunim erom wef A
”!lacilobaid woH“ .eelg ni
,uoy fo hcae rof eip evah I“
,kcoc rieht fo hcni yreve degassam spil riehT
”.live rof yadot cigam kcalb fo tol a tsevrah ot tnaw eW“
,ti revo lla derebbols dna
,derettulf hcamots s’nairE
si yrots s’yadoT dna
daeh s’ahtagA ,meht dniheB
,ssa rieht tsniaga kcoc debrab rieht decalp yeht nehT
,edis eninac rieht gnola nwod wap kcalb rieht deliart yehT
.erusaelp htiw gniredduhs seidob rieht
”.retteb leef uoy ekam ll’tI
.noisurtni eht tsniaga gnithgif ,dnuorg eht otni gud swap-toof reh dna
”,eiraed ,doog os sleef tahT“
.seert sselfael eht ffo
.erutpar fo eton gnol eno otni
.tnemom taht ni evila leef ruf eht edam revetahw otni cigam eht wolf ot dah yehT
ylwolS sklaW ohW
—detpurretni cimagA ”!nataS roF“
.msaisuhtne gums hcum oot raf htiw
.ega ruoy saw I nehw slegna gninommus emit drah a dah I
.seidob s’rehto hcae rof evol s’oppih dna noil eht ni derahs evah ot dalg
.cigam krad reh ni yaw gnol a emoc s’ehS
,nevoc eht ni enoyreve leef dluoc yehT
.ti otni gnillaf flesruoy leef uoy taht
.htuom rieht ni kcoc s’edurtreG leef dluoc yehT
.ni denael yeht os
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro ,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.azziP ruoy ni seivohcnA skaenS ohW yehT
.pu thgiarts gnikcits kcoc dettonk rieht
ylthgils gniohce
meht ta kool enoyreve evah dna duol tuo ti yas dluoc yeht tuB
.yrtsap derettub dna ssenteews llaf fo teuquob a
.gnitsorf nworb htiw sekacpuc kcalb fo sreit lareves gnilaever
.skcoc dna sregnif dehcnelc sanigav rieht
.enoyreve dehctaw yeht sa ssa rieht tsniaga gnisserp wap rehto rieht dna ,kcoc rieht dnuora wap s’tar etihw rieht leef dluoc yehT
ssa reh deggaw ehs—
erom gnihton detnaw nairE
.gnilggij ylleb gib sih
.meht tsniaga swap s’maS gnippart
.dias cirE ”,laer ooT“
kcalb dna tsav os si yks eht nehw ekil
.lla ti devol dna
”,eiraed ,esruoc fO“ ”?esimorP“
.no dereidlos edurtreG
,eriseD fo ytitnauQ ehT
.anigav rieht did kcoc rieht sa
,sekoj dab dna live ot dettimmoc dairt a roF“
”,ssorg ton—live er’eW“
”.eip elbatceled ruoy tsiser reven dluoc I“
.deraelc dnim rieht dna denaorg nairE ”.won retteb llA“
,revo dellor ylwols ahtagA
”,tol a enihw od erus lla’y
”,eriflleh sa tcefrep sa era esehT“
.niarb rieht depolevne dna
.wonk t’ndid yehT
”?ti seod ,reisae yna steg reven ti ,lleH“
.ti demusnoc dna thguoht tnerehoc yna no decnuop yeht
.wap eninac rieht htiw yltneg ecaf reh dekorts dna
.cigam krad s’thginot gnisu
detevlev eht ot gnulc neht
”.erotS yrecorG eht ta deeN uoY gnihT tahT fo tnorF ni sdnatS ohW yehT
.decniw cirE dna maS taht hguone duol dehgis nairE
.lufrewop dna daorb flow yerg eht
,enecs retfa enecs gnihctaw
”.ssa rieht hsaw ot woh wonk dna etuc er’yeht tsael ta tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,osrot sti yb ydob nedlog rieht debbarg yeht nehT
.spih rieht tsniaga gnimmals elzzum rieht
smra rieht hguorht ti tnes dna ,cigam krad eht rof flesmeht edisni nwod dehcaer
.hself otni gniggid swalc rieht
”.syad eseht seigro cigam kcalb ,live yojne ohw klof tsenoh ,doog dnif ot drah os s’tI“ .dekst ahtagA ”.yadot
,delims nairE .ecno rof—
krims a htiw dias nairE
.xivrec rieht sa peed sa tnew dna
,tnemom a rof ssa rieht fo tuo eugnot hguor ,llams rieht dellup yehT .ysatsce saw tI
,ylgnidnammoc dias edurtreG ”,eiraeD“
,eip egral a dleh taht reniatnoc a denepo ehS
”?nwaL ruoY no pooP goD sevaeL ohW yehT gnivres er’ew tegrof uoy diD ?tnemom eciN“
tnereffid erusaelp hcae ,ecno ta lla dellif erew dna dellif yehT
”,ekil erom ,kcoc rof gniyarP“
.ecils a meht dednah edurtreG sa
,flesmeht ssik otni denael yehT
.eciov s’maS ni dias yeht
elzzum reh htaeneb rehtegot swap reh gnignirb
”.gnuoy eht morf yrehcaert tcepxe slegnA
desaelp yllufepoh dna thgir tlef revetahw otni delddum tsuj yeht tub
,dedisbus rethgual eht nehW
”,laiceps taht t’nsi eip ym ,won ,hO“
,ni lla ti koot yehT
htiw desuffus saw elims live
,dab os ti etsat ot detnaw yehT
,htaerb sih gnihctac
.regguR .P .B yb ”eiraeD ,nataS“
,dias ehs ”,eiraed ,yrreJ“
.etalfed ot detrats ydaerla dah tonk eht hguoht
.ssarg eht hguorht dekcilf liat sih dna
.yadot gnihctaw ,hu ,yb cigam erom etareneg ll’I kniht I“
.derelloh ahtagA ”?elytS“ deksa maS
.thgin eht hguorht tuc eciov niht reH
.drah ,dezeeuqs yehT
,drawrof delwarc dna eugnot hguor rieht tuo dellup yehT
,wonk uoy fo emos sA“
.deirc edurtreG ”!esaelp
* ”.yssup rof yarp osla I ,wonk llew uoy sA“
,dah yeht erom eht dnA .noissap ,ygrene
eno siht piks nac uoy
osrot wolley rieht fo edis rehtie no sevooh rieht decalp dna doots yehT
devlossid yeht litnu retsaf dna retsaf emac sehsalf ehT
.dnuorg eht no mih dial ehs sa dias edurtreG
,delwoh yehT .detsurht dna
,flesmih yb gnidnats tar etihw eht ta revo gnikool
dennirg cirE—”yas d’I
.erom ecno ngier dluow livE
cimagA ”,yadot uoy evres ot erusaelp a s’tI“
.ecno ta lla gnikrab dna ,gnissih ,gnitnurg
.tey ydaer etiuq ton
tnaw reve dluoc yeht lla—detnaw reve yeht lla saw ti
.desopxe saw ssa rieht litnu yltneg dehsup dna
”,cirE ,ereht uoy tog s’ehS“ ”.uoy
.ecaf nedlog rieht delddarts swaptoof kcalb rieht dna ,doots neht
,nairE yeht erew regnol oN
rednerrus fo sehsalF
nairE .rewop fo bew
,swap eninoil rieht tsniaga dehsiuqs ylleb s’oppih eht fo taf tfos eht woh devol yehT
.meht fo hcae yb desu eb ot naht
”.gnorts worg ot tae ot deen uoy ekil sgniht elttil gnuoY“ .dias edurtreG
,kcoc denips rieht ta derats yeht sA
.stsaerb enipul rieht tsniaga
.lleh fo stip tsepeed eht ni draeh eb dluoc kcams eht taht
.anigav rieht dellif kcoc rieht elihw eugnot rieht dnuora hcnelc ssa rieht tlef dna
,niap htiw ediw erew seye reH
,sevaw sa ,erusserp sa
”?rentrap a evah uoy od“
.dezeeuqs yeht sa delppir sba eninoil rieht fo elcsum drah eht woh dna
,waj dedraeb rieht fo enil gnorts eht ta delevram yehT
.spih eht yb fles nedlog rieht debbarg dna ssa rieht fo tuo kcoc denips rieht dellup yehT
,stnemtaert recnac s’egroeG no sgnivas rieht lla tneps yehT
,kcab wolley rieht gnola gnibbur tsehc kcalb rieht
,rehtona ni ssa s’xof a ,wap eno ni nroh llub a
,tnemom a rof yzzid meht edam dlrow eht fo ssenllits eht dna
.ahtagA ta derats cirE
elggurts reh fo ygrene eht debrosba nairE tuB
kcoc denips rieht dehsup yehT
.kcoc dnuora desolc taorht rieht dna
.yltcefrep decnalab lla
slirdnet elprup eht ,yllaniF
.nomed a nommus ot hguone duol derepsihw cirE
,teef sih ot yaw sih dekrow ylwols eH ”.edurtreG“