.redael kcap eht htiw tabmoc ni degagne dnuora denrut ylneddus eninac eht
)seirotsd2( ta egap yrrufoS sih dna laicos.yksb.goddliwd2@
.mih naht rellams eb ylbissop dluoc ti
,esolc os kcap remrof eht htiW
ta yks eulb no mih wollof nac uoY.sevitcepsrep
.ylppus doof rieht eldniwd dluoc
wob yalp a edam eH .erutaerc wen
.mih dehcaorppa ylluferac god dliw eht sa
.skcil etanoitceffa otni denrut scitna deltserw rieht stnemom wef a nihtiW
,stnahpele sa hcus yerp regral egnellahc yltcerid reven dluoc owt eht elihW
.tnuh ot god dliw eht rof
,eert a ot txen htap trid eht gnola tuO
.eugnot tfos sih htiw dnuow eht naelc yltneg ot drawrof denael dna
erutseg evissimbus eht fo eciton koot enipluv der ehT
,deniatniam llew erew sevreser doof rieht
.snoitcudortni s’rehto hcae ediug ot eson rieht dewolla dna
.erutraped sih ecnis deldniwd dah srebmun rieht llet dluoc eninac ehT
.stcejorp gnitirw erutuf rof
daeh sti dewob yltneg god dliw ehT
.skcatta eht fo tsrow eht fo
.worrub eert daed eht dnoyeb tuo derutnev owt eht revenehw yllaicepse
.slamina deppart ta detnih netfo segac tliub namuH
,pu tilps dah kcap ehT
,dnal siht ot evitan ton saw xof der eht fi nevE
,ffo mih ekahs ot elba saw eh elihW
tnecs eht thguac eson sih
sgel dnih sih no pu doots xof ehT
.tsurt s’xof eht tuo thguos dna
.sdnammoc labrev sih ot dednopser t’ndah xof der eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sevitcepsrep gniticxe dna wen ecneirepxe ot sredaer emirp ot yaw a sa gnitirw sesu ohw
,dnuorg eht ot nwod erutsop sih tpek god dliw ehT
.sretem wef a rof yerp sti detnuh dna
,saw tsaeb siht revemohW
.mih revo lla tnecs xof sih bur ot dneirf wen sih dewolla god dliw ehT
.tiab sa detca eh elihw
sdnarts der fo stnih dleh yrtsepat deroloc-itlum s’god dliw ehT
,egac eht fo ezis llams eht ot eud dnA
.tiaw nwo sih htaenrednu delkcub dna delbmuts noos redael kcap eht
,tnecs ngierof s'rehtona eno ot demotsucca emoceb ylno ton ot siht did yehT
.skeew rof god dliw eht derehtob dah taht skcit eht ta yawa kcip ot mih dewolla hteet dna elzzum euqinu s’xof ehT
epacse ot emit hguone noinapmoc xof sih evig ot rO
.mih htiw seit tuc ot yrassecen ti tlef yeht
yojne esaelP  .remrahC
slliks gnitnuh fo kcal s’god dliw eht rof t’nsaw tI
.nerhterb sih fo skaeuqs dna sllac railimaf eht draeh eninac eht
.xof eht deerf dna elzzum sih htiw
,llams s'ti fi dnA
”sdneirF hannavaS“
taht fo esuaceb dnA
.kcap remrof s’god dliw eht morf sgnikram tnecs
.setats lanoitome rieht eguag ot tub
.roivaheb s’god dliw eht yduts ot sruof lla no tas dna
worrob laitini rieht morf tuo raf erutnev ot diarfa oot saw enipluv ehT
rorroh htiw denediw seye siH
.os gniod eunitnoc ot thguos dna
.ni desolc yllaudarg tcap remrof eht
.oud eht dnuora elcric imes a mrof dna ecap
xof eht ot esahc nevig dah eerht
kcap sih tnorfnoc ot thguos god dliw ehT
,eninac eht morf sdorp dna sekop lufyalp wef a retfA
,xof cennef a fo taht delbmeser serutaef stI
sehctarcs elpitlum htiw yawa emoc dah eninac eht
,tniop tnorf eht koot syawla eninac eht dnA
.erutaerc eht no decnuop dna drawrof sgel sih deniarps god dliw eht
.yawyna tuocs ot yrassecen saw ti tlef eh
.pu tilps ylkciuq owt eht dna daeh sih dewob eninac ehT
.eert dedahs eht htaenrednu eltserw ot nageb owt eht
deklats god dliw eht
hcamots s’god dliw eht pu delevart lworg lamirp A  sivaD suiraD yb
.taoc retuo sih ot gnulc taht
,yalp ni degagne god dliw eht nehw dnA
,noitpo rehto on htiW
.nwo sih tsniaga ydob sti delioc ylthgit xof eht nehw decar traeh siH
.ylbatrofmoc tae ot meht wolla scimanyd gnitnuh euqinu rieht
.kcap wen sih rof noinapmoc a sa evres dluoc xof der eht spahrep
.swap rieht dnuora loop ot nageb dna
.sdnal eht ot evitan ton esoht yllaicepse
,yerp tnedor llams a naht rehtaR
,rotciv eht sa sutats sih etipseD
.noisiced s’kcap eht denimreted taht gnirpsffo ecudorp dna
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer
.noinapmoc sih nopu seirujni eht dettops eh
eert eht ot delf xof ehT
noititepmoc eht taht deraef oud eht
.mih detpecca ylluf dah noinapmoc wen sih hguoht sa tlef eninac eht ,yaw a nI
.lavivrus mret gnol rieht ot taerht a noitaercorp fo kcal eht deviecrep yehT
sekirts eht fo tsrow eht diova ot sgel ynniks sih delffuhs eH .skcatta otni
,ydob s’god dliw tsactuo eht no redael kcap remrof rieht fo tnecs eht htiW
.erofeb deretnuocne reven eh gnihtemos saw ti sa
.devivrus yeht fi
,dael eht sa god dliw eht htiW
.tnecs s’rehto hcae detpoda yeht sa
,egatnavda ezis eht htiw nevE
,swolb ,sehctarcs dedart yehT
meht dehtab duolc tsud yvaeh A
.meht kram ot yaw a sa sburhs ybraen dna
sevlesmeht ot yrotirret fo noitces llams a dah yeht dna
,dedulcnoc ksat sih htiW  .sselnoitom
.tesnus eht fo noitcelfer eht morf deremmilg egac latem a
,sliart tliub namuh raen levart ot sksir era ereht hguoht nevE
.srebmun rieht niht ot
stnap enipluv der ehT
elttab eht retfa pu teem ot erehw wonk dluow owt eht
,sivaD suiraD yb ”sdneirF hannavaS“
,liat der thgirb eht no desucof resal seye sih htiW
.mih fo pot no tas
.rehtegot tset eurt tsrif rieht dessap dah yehT
.evol dna htmraw fo yruf a ni edilloc ot seidob rieht dewolla dna sruof lla no tas ylpmis eh dnA
s’elam regnorts eht ward ot deirt god dliw eht sa
,nwo sih llac ot kcap on htiW
.yerp sih eb ot detcepxe eh erutaerc a t’nsaw tI .detatiseh eh
.taoc ruf s’eninac eht otni flesti deirub elzzum s’enipluv rellams eht
seert suoirav ta dehctarcs xof ehT
,sruof lla no doots owt eht sa dnA
,kcap remrof s’god dliw eht ot resolc tog yeht ecnO
,resolc serutaef sti yduts dluoc god dliw eht erofeB
.sdnoces erem nihtiw skram etib dna
,tnemom feirb a roF
.og dluohs yeht erehw ot sa
,yb emoc ot tluciffid doof htiW
.xof rellams eht ot dettimbus eh
.stoor eert dnuorgrednu eht ot txen deldduc gnineve eht dedne owt eht dnA
siht htiw sdneirf emoceb ot ytinutroppo na was god dliw ehT
.rebmuls rieht erofeb emit eht ssap ot noisses gnimoorg yldneirf a derahs yehT
,rellevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tsehc s’god dliw eht tsniaga dennip swap llams sih tpek dna
rood msinahcem part eht detfil eh
.esion worran a dna
srae detniop llat htiw ,lamina yrruf der a fo thgis eht yb
rednow htiw erats dluow eninac eht semitemoS
oirt god dliw eht
.doof rof dehcraes eh sa
.emoh rieht llac ot
,denaelc dnuow eht htiW
.srehto eht htiw rap no erew yeht sa
dnuorg eht ssorca deppets ylthgil swap siH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
erutaerc wen eht ot noissimbus etelpmoc dewohs eH
.edis s’rehto hcae yb eb syawla dluow owt eht
srebmem elamef eht htiw elgnim-oc ot ytilibani s’god dliw eht saw ti ,revewoH
,thgin eht rof tser ot ecalp elbatrofmoc efas a dnuof owt eht nehW
,rehtegot tneps yeht thgin yreve roF
,dehsiruonlam dna deriT
,denruter eninac eht nehW
kaeuqs llams a desaeler dna
resolc deppets ylluferac yeht
.noitarolpxe yksir eht htrow saw ti
,tniop cificeps a ta kcap eht ffo dnef ton dluoc yeht fI
.etacinummoc ot elba eb dluow yeht sepoh eht ni
taoc s’xof eht fo trap tsemraw eht otni flesti deltsen neht eson s’god dliw ehT
eert daed dekram eht sdrawot daeh sih denoitom dna
.gnieelf morf xof eht detneverp hcihw msinahcem part latem a no kcuts saw sbmil dnih sti fo eno hguohT
saw tsrif ehT .oud eht rof degreme dah sngis gninraw sa devil trohs saw ecaep riehT
,noziroh eht gnola tes ot nageb nus eht nehW
.eninac eht htiw pu tem dna nwod debmilc ylluferac eh
.srentrap gnitnuh tnellecxe rof edam owt eht
laem ysae na eb yllaitnetop dluoc lamina deppart eht tnaem ti
.kcen s’redael kcap eht otno etib ot deganam dna drawrof depael eninac eht ,gninepo na was eh nehW
,efas tlef xof eht nehW
seitilamrof htiw rehtob t'ndid
yllausiv dneirf xof sih ediug ot deirt god dliw eht
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa reeuq kcalb a
sessol rieht tuc dah
,slamina dliw sdroffa ylerar erutan gnihtemoS
,srebmun roirepus rieht etipseD
ti evah t'ndluow yeht ,meht rof dnA
yrotirret rieht fo strikstuo eht no dehcaorcne ylwols dah yehT
tsrif ta tnecs eht fo ekam ot tahw wonk t’ndid eninac ehT
der fo edahs tnaillirb a dessessop ruf stI
.elbarapesni emoceb dah owt eht
efil tnalp deird eht ni neddih erugif sih tpek god dliw ehT
,dnim s’eninac eht nI
.kcap eht ot nedrub a erew ohw esoht dehs ot yrassecen ti tlef puorg eht
.gnilzzun etamitni ot denepeed dah skcil ehT
.seye neerg ekil-meg esoht tsniaga detsartnoc hcihw
redael kcap remrof sih detiab god dliw eht sa
,lluf tpek syawla erew seilleb s’owt ehT
.snoitpo owt ylno erew ereht
dehtacsnu ylniam erew yeht ees ot deveiler
gnitrofmoc eb ot tnecs eht dnuof eH .tpels eh sa
dedulcnoc ylkciuq dah elttab ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.rehtie sllac s’god dliw eht  fo noitcerid eht ot detniop t’ndah srae s’xof eht
.etaf sih fo erawa edam erew yeht
,ylsuoiruc daeh sih detlit xof ehT
.htnom dnoces eht yb pihsnoitaler citoibmys a naht erom saw cimanyd riehT
.erutan ni ngierof hguoht
yad eht nihtiw dna
.yrotirret rieht ni dlohtoof a mialc dluoc yeht erofeb
.eert eht morf ffo meht esahc ot deganam eh
,edam erew sllac labrev ynam woh rettam on ,revewoH
.kcap sih morf detarapes saw eh retfa laem tsal sih ecnis keew a neeb dah tI
,oud eht ecaf yam segnellahc rehto tahw rettam oN
.sevil nwo rieht fo ksir eht ta neve ,noitcetorp s’rehto hcae tuo thguos dah yehT
,yrrow htiw deremmilg seye neerg s’enipluv ehT
,dleif nepo eht nI
,sivaD suiraD yb ”sdneirF hannavaS“ saw sihT      .yaw rehto yna
ssarg llat eht tsgnoma dial redael kcap eht sa
daeh sih fo edis eht nwod dewolf dah doolB
.rehto hcae ot nward erew owt eht erom eht
.sruof lla no dnats ot nageb eh sa snoitom sih dnatsrednu ot demees dna pu dekrep daeh s’enipluv ehT .daeh dluohs yeht noitcerid eht ot sa htron daeh sih detniop eninac eht
,retnuocne thgin yreve htiw sA
.meht tsgnoma tfel elamef eno ylno saw ereht dna
,liat der yffulf a fo espmilg a thguac eh nehw teY
dniw nwod deklaw dna
evila hcum yrev llits saw redael tcap ehT
.evisnopsernu deniamer enipluv eht
.erutaerc rehtona fo
.erutaerc citoxe eht ot nward syawla flesmih dnuof eh
.erofeb nees reven dah eh
,drawrof yad taht morf dnA
.gnineve eht rof deriter dna
,tnemredliweb sih ot ,teY
,lla fo tsegnartS
.slliks eht pu dekcip ylkciuq xof eht dna
,hguone esolc saw owt eht neewteb ecnatsid eht tlef eh nehW
.eno yb eno ffo dekcip dna dednuorrus ylisae eb dluoc owt eht
.ezis llarevo ni regral tpecxe
eliga erom saw xof eht
.hannavas eht otni delf dna
semehcs dna skcirt gnitnuh deyolpme xof eht sa
.taoc ruf s’xof der eht nwod kcils retteb ot mih dewolla
eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
.esop evissergga na ni doots dna
.epacse ot deirt dna swap tnorf sti htiw yawa flesti dekcik xof der eht
.pu daeh sih dekrep dna
.wollof ot noinapmoc xof sih ot tuo dellac god dliw eht
.yawa sretem wef a
,noitnetta sih teg ot redluohs s’xof der eht deppat eh retfA
.ebol rae thgir sih no
.yerp laitnetop sa evres dluoc yeht snaem ti
.nepo elzzum sih tpek dna
.noinapmoc sih ot esolc kcuts dna
.noitnetta sih thguac dah tcejbo ynihs a ,esirprus sih oT
eugnot eninac daorb erom s’god dliw eht ,nruter ni dnA
.slevart rieht tuohguorht dnuorg eht no doof fo selip ssot lliw snamuh ,semitemoS
,thginot laem a dnif ton dluoc god dliw eht fi nevE
,seye dekcol owt ehT
hannavaS eht fo segde raf eht ot mih dehsinab dah yehT
,llik eht dettimmoc god dliw eht erofeB
.god dliw tsactuo eht detegrat redael kcap eht sa
,tcap remrof sih tsgnoma stnecs euqinu net gnidnif fo daetsnI
.ruof ot nwod deldniwd dah ti
.tnecs sih edih ot
.esion laminim edam dna
.ecalp ni deyats eh sa hcuot eht ot mraw emaceb srae egral siH
,ecnatsid hguone nevig nehW
si yrots s’yadoT dna
hsag egral a dna
,deliops erew selbahsirep eht fi nevE
.rebmuls peed a otni ffo dezod owt eht erofeb elbatrofmoc teg ot xof eht dewolla eH
.dehsinif saw eh litnu
redro larutan s'erutan deifed dah yehT
.llew sa taoc ruf sih fo strap emos denroda osla xof eht dnA
.sliart namuh niam eht morf yawa htron yaw rieht daeh owt eht
srekcatta eht llats dluow xof eht taht tsurt si od dluoc eninac eht llA
sezis suoirav fo s’god dliw ruoF
.dneirf wen sih htiw taeh ydob sih erahs ot thguos dna
.mih ot txen pu eldduc ot thguos xof eht
.ssarg llat eht tsgnoma dih dna nwod dehcuorc eh
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ni kcap eht ni
tnuh ot ysae saw yerp hcihw mih wohs dluow eninac ehT
.tuo meht evird dna kcap eht ffo dnef oT
redael kcap riehT
,god.ecioveht ta
,stnuh lufsseccus rieht retfA
eert daed eht htaenrednu worrub tfihsekam eht edisni debmilc yeht
liat s’noinapmoc sih ta ylsuovren deppin xof eht ,hcihw oT
.liat tnagele sih deggaw dna
.yalp erom rof noitnetta sih teg ot liat s’eninac eht ta deppin xof eht
,egac latem eht dehcaer god dliw eht nehW
.tuo meht erit ot deunitnoc dna
.hcaer fo tuo s’god dliw eht tpek taht seuqinhcet evitpada dna ytilibom retteb rieht desu enipluv der ehT .eert eht sdrawot dedaeh ylkciuq eninac suoirotciv eht
detnorfnoc daetsni saw eh
.yrotirret sih fo segde retuo eht gnola levart ot deunitnoc eninac dezis-dim eht
,daeh sih detfil eh nehW
,mih ekil lammam a saw tI
rehtona eno otno dehs staoc ruf euqinu riehT
.enituor a fo noitasnes tnatsnoc gnitrofmoc a saw ereht
.esop s’xof eht neve naht rewol
god dliw reivaeh dna regral eht erofeb delggurts ylfeirb owt ehT