.rac eht fo tuo deppets eh sa dias mom sih
.tsae eht ot yks gninekrad eht gnieye ,decap ttum yksuh gniyarg ehT
.ssengnihton otni yawa detlem yeht
”ytuaeb“ ekil sdrow tub ,lufituaeb neeb evah dluohs taht mih dnuora yawhcra na detaerc seert kao tnaiG
.detsub s’eniM .moor ym rof eno wen a deen …hu I“ .deksa eh
,xob tevlev eht dehctans ,tekcop taoc sih otni deppils tI
”.eno nekorb dlo eht htiw kcits ot evah tsuj ll’I sseuG
.dlrow siht otni mih dewollof t’ndah
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.aet revo pu hctac nac ew neht dna edisni ffuts siht teg em pleh ,no emoC“
puoL nemraC yb detide
fi sa nepo gnuws rood ehT .dleh ti tub
,emarf eht rednu morf pu peerc ot nageb ssenkrad fo slirdnet elttiL
t’nsaw ti ,ylnO .esuoheraw eht fo noitrop niam eht morf elbaliava saw thgil elttil tahw gnitcelfer saw tI
.mih htaeneb elbmurc t’ndid yeht taht desirprus ylgnissap saw eh dna ,waprednu dekaerc spets ehT
.esproc gnittor a morf gnippils hself ekil sehcnarb eht morf nwod deppird ssoM
,tnemom a rof sevael daed eht ni dnuora deppils eh sa
,retaw dloc otni gnipmuj ekil tsomla tlef tI
”,ffuts ym lla gnilles si mailliW nos gnihton rof doog ym snaem ti esoppus I
.ylkciuq daerps erif ehT
,eninac tsomla saw ecaf s’tI
emarf s’ti yb rorrim eht debbarg yaR
.llehs tuo tnrub a won saw ,oga gnol dlrow siht dehctid gnivah ytuaeb ,tub ,noisnam lufituaeb a neeb ecno evah thgim tahw detanimulli thgilhsalf siH
,gninaorg erew ti fi sa
”?raed ,yako uoy erA“
taht erus saw yaR taht ylduol os dehceercs tsaeb ehT
,eveihca dluoc ydob derit sih desirprus saw eh deeps a htiW
.edis rehto eht no ehtaerb llits dluoc eh tub
kao gnittor fo tnecs ehT
.seno gnivil naht soboh lartceps erom yb deldnahnap neeb d’eh ,nwotnwoD
.edart eht ekam dna
.keirhs yltsaeb eht draeh eH
.mih no kcehc ot ecilop eht gnillac eb dluow srobhgien sih
.meht ees t’ndid eh dneterp ot deirt eh
.dloc elbanosaesnu eht etipsed gnimaercs ,seert eht ni gnas sadaciC
-ti kniht ot detah yaR--tsomla saw tI
.dne no doots ydob sih no ruf yreve ,esuoh dlo eht dehcaorppa eh sA
.tsenialp eht yldediced saw eno siht dna
.ykoops htiw dedaj ytterp saw eh dna ,mih ot neve ,ykoops saw tI
.denmad eb ytivarg ,sdrawpu mih hcnual ot sgel sih rof noitavitom hguone saw tahT
,tekcaj rehtael kcalb sih fo tekcop eht otni xob eht deppils eH
.ylsuoiruc tuo dekeep tac dega elddim a dna ,retal tnemom a nepo dekaerc rood ehT
.rorrim eht otno reilf gnimalf eht gnippord
.ynnarg deltnurgsid lacipyt ruoy t’nsaw ereh kcab saw revetahw taht noicipsus gnikaens eht dah eh tub
.esnes dluoc tbuod on
.ylrae siht pu erew srecneulfni aidem laicos dna stsihcosam ylnO
s’eman yM“ .dias namow eht
”?uoy ekaw I did ,traehteews yrros m’I“
.ti dnoyeb thgin yllihc eht otni dna ssalg eht hguorht thgir desahp dnah sih dna
)eno naht erom eb ot dah ereht taht won yb denrael d’eh( gninetsil saw dog revetahw ot deyarp eH
.yrc ot nageb dna
?yddib dlo na hcus llits I ma yhw ,esac eht s’taht fI“ .dias siroD ”,ees I“ ”.efil
”.kcab emac ohw enoyna nwonk reven
.ti dnif reve dluow eno on erehw ti yrub dna esnaelc ot evah dna
,relevart wollef ruoy
,rood eht dehcaorppa eh sa thgiew sih htaeneb gas ot demees hcrop ehT
.htiw ti hsams ot yvaeh gnihtemos rof gnikool ,thguoht yaR .epoN
s’tI“ .draobhsad eht gnittap ,dehgis yaR ”,yddub ,wonk I“
,semitemos diova ot drah saw tI
,ylimE ees og ot gniog m’I“
.ssalg eht fo tuo gnihcaer dnah kcalb ,dewalc a was eh
.kcab kool ot tuoba t’nsaw yaR
.yliggorg deksa eh ”?olleH“
.ot deirt eh ,tsael ta rO
.ti ekam ot gniog t’nsaw eH
.ni ti gnignirb saw I sa ti deppord I tuB“ .dehgual yaR
.ereh nrub ot tfel gnihton saw erehT
yletinifed tsomla saw tub lio ekil dekool tahw fo emos htiw gnola swalc sti morf deppord slraep ehT
,stceffe lanosrep s’rehtom ruoy fo emos su thguorb yltnecer mailliW rehtorb ruoY“ .dias eh
”-ezilaer t’ndid I ,nam yrroS“ .desruc eH
.erofeb tnemom a neeb dah daeh sih erehw nwod emac
taorht sih ni doolb detsat eH
.ylsuovren dehgual yaR
”.stsohg ees t’nac elpoep tsoM
”.reh fo duorp m’I dnA“ .dias siroD
.ti ekil thgim uoy thguoht I“
,teertS eltryM ot tnew yaR ,yad txen ehT
,ssarg dehcrocs eht tuoba droldnal sih htiw tahc gninrom ylrae na
.desserd ydaerla saw eh tsael tA
.meht teg ot tihsllub fo tol a hguorht enog d’eH
.rehtom sih raen erehwyna saw siht lleh eht revetahw tnaw t’ndid dna tihs siht fo htrow sraey evif-ytnewt nees d’eh tuB
”,siroD ,tseb ym od
.slraep eht barg ot roolf eht ot evod eH .dias yaR
,kcalb laocrahc saw doow ehT
”.rehtie ekawa eb annaw t’nod I ,ylrae oot
.sgniht ypeerc dekil syawla ev’uoY
,dlo sraey ytnewt tuoba eb ot dekool taht flesreh fo noisrev a no gnilttes erofeb noisivelet ycitats a hguorht gniyalp egami na ekil yzzuf emoceb ot demees ehS
.niaga rorrim eht otni ylsuoiruc derats eH
,ruoh siht ta neve ,hcihw tsafkaerb rof otirrub nezorf a devaworcim eh ,nehctik eht ni ydaerla saw eh  ecniS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
daer DI rellac ehT
.wohs tsetal s’dnab s’dneirf sih rof
,saw ti sa revo dehcnuh neve
”.ereh pu ekow I neht
ot retupmoc sih ta nwod tas
.esnepxe sih ta hgual tsal eno gnivah erew seert gums ehT
,steknirt dlo fo ytnelp
”?neht sneppah tahW“
yawevird trid s’esuoh noitcua eht otni dellup eH
,yrrehc gniredloms eht tuo depmots ylraen
.rail a t’nsaw eh tub ,sgniht ynam neeb evah yam eH
”,hcum yrev reh evol I taht reh lleT“
.ssengnihton otni yawa dedaf dnuos eht ,ylwols ,nehT
,stsohg htiw gnilaed htiw enif saw yaR
”,esuoH noitcuA snoS & yecarG ta er’uoY“
.niahc sti no tuo gniws hctaw eht tel eH
dnalrag samtsirhC ycnaf a ekil swalc sti revo depard slraep ehT  .daeh
”.tuo ti kcehc annaw I ,sexob eht fo eno ni looc gnihtemos was I“ .dias yaR
rehtona ni nettog evah tsum stnerap siH
.aedi taerg a saw
.dias mom s’yaR ”,emit ni tsuJ“
.nepo llits saw emoh kcab latrop-rorrim eht taht
.detnaw ti tahw wenk dnah ehT
”!ereh er’uoy ssendoog knahT“
.dehgual ehS ”?gniht dlo tahT“ ”.detsub
.rehtomdnarg ym ot degnoleb yehT
,yawhtap tserof a fo weiv detarutased a saw ssalg ytrid eht dnoyeb ;moor eht gnitcelfer
.deraeppasid ehs ,taht htiW
,rorrim live na ot tsoh gniyalp fo aedi eht detah eH
niar ot gniog s’ti ekil skool ti tub ,net ta krow otni emoc ot gerG rof tiaw d’I
.dnuorg eht gniyduts ,dias namow eht ”,hO“
,steehsdeb sih ni delgnat dial yecarG yaR deman ttum detaoc-elrem A .MA8 saw tI
.ssalg eht dehcaorppa eh
.rof gnikool saw eh tahw dnuof eH
.sdoow eht rof ti dekoob dna teef sih ot derebmalc eH
,puoL kcaZ yb ”ssalG gnikooL eht wercS“   yojne esaelP
.rorrim eht sdrawot tpael eH
tsehc reh ot meht degguh ehS
”,wonk yllaer t’nod I ,lleW“
,hctaw eht derefforp eH
.moolrieh ylimaf a
,dnoyeb taerg eht ro ,thgil eht otni ,seY“
.od ot lleh eht tahw tuo erugif ot yrt
”?gniog elttek eht teg I dluohS“
.sdraobpuc sih dniheb devil taht sehcaorkcoc fo ylimaf eht yawa eracs tsael ta thgim ti fo sseniree eht spahrep gnikniht nehctik sih ni pu ti tes eH
.etanimal deniats ssorca gniddiks saw eh ylnedduS
.hctaw eht tuo gnidloh ,dias yaR ”,ereH“
;stirips htiw gnilaed ot regnarts on saw yaR
.taorht sih ni deloop ti fo eroM
.deksa eh ”?ylimE uoy erA“
.hguoht ,gnihton naht retteB .ylbaborP
edisni hcuoc eht gard ot yaR rof detiaw yletilop yks ehT
.noitcua eht rof ffuts fo hcnub a ffo pord nam a dah tsuj I dna ,nwot fo tuo s’rehtaf ruoy tuB“ .dias ehs
.secnelitsep dna sraw fo tluser a sa sliob ytsan ni derevoc ro seloh tellub htiw dellif stsohg htiw ysuol
reilf delpmurc a eb ot deneppah hcihw ,repap fo eceip tseraen eht debbarg dna niaga edisni kcab nar eH
.pohs tfarchctiw lacol eht morf thguob d’eh seldnac etihw gnisnaelc eht fo eno til eH .rorrim pmad a
.esrow hcum os mih ta gnikool saw ti taht tcaf eht edam taht tub ,seye evah t’ndid yletinifed tI
,nehctik sih morf akdov fo elttob doog yltcefrep a dehctans yaR  .dlrow sti ot latrop gnisolc eht epacse ot delggurts tnatibahni s’ti sa detarbiv emarf s’rorrim ehT
.slraep ym dniF“ .dias ehs ”,yaR“
.mrala rac a dekcimim dribgnikcom a sa llew sa tuoba efil dekcimim taht sepahs gnilbmahs ,dirroh otni sevlesmeht egnarra ot elba erew tub ,evila neeb reven dah taht sgnihT
.ylthgils rood eht gninepo ,dias ehs ”,seY“
”,tneinevnocni ythgim s’taht ,lleW“
,guh a ni rethguad reh dnuora depparw
”,mom ,oot uoy evoL“ ”!uoy
,seye yna evah t’ndid tI
,swap reh otni slraep eht koot yltneg dna tuo dehcaer ylimE
,dray sih ni serifnob lagelli gnitrats ton tuoba spoc eht htiw klat thgindim a gniwollof
”,esuoH noitcuA snoS & yecarG fo ,yecarG yaR m’I“ ”?uoy era ohW“
,meht teg ot lleh hguorht enog d’eH  .delims yaR
.uoy thguorb mailliW sgniht eht htiw eb ot evah yehT
,floWcaM boR si sihT
namow a saw erehT
”.no evom nac uoy rO .ekil d’uoy tahw s’taht fi ,tnuah ot ecalp a esoohc nac uoy ,rehtag I tahw morF“ .dettimda yaR
.mrof ynniks-oot a dnuora depparw-knirhs niks kcalb-diov fo esnapxe htooms a tsuj
,yltnelis elbatnrut sih no nups drocer A
thgieh sih eciwt saw tI .lluks sti fo tuo delarips snroh evissaM
”?thgir ,iahc a ekil d’uoY“
.htuom reh gnirevoc swap reh ,depsag ylimE ”!hO“
.efil ni flesruoy fo yromem a tsuj si mrof sihT“ .dias yaR
,gnikil s’yaR rof thgirb oot yleritne saw nus ehT  ”.ekawa m’I ,yakO“
.delims eH ”.mom ,sknahT“
.tsael ta ,dlrow sih rO .dlrow laer eht ot rohcna na ,etteragic sih fo gard rehtona koot eH
.emit tsal eno rorrim eht dehcaorppa eh sa
.mih gnikcom erew seert ehT .erew yehT
.mih depleh dah reveohw ot detuohs eh ”!uoy knahT“
.puoL kcaZ yb ”ssalG gnikooL eht wercS“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
,dias eh ”,ffo kcuF“
.retteb tlef eH .pu ekow eh nehw
”,ti eveileb reven ll’uoy ,hO“
.ti gniw ot evah d’eH
.eciov ynit a ni ,deksa namow eht ”?no evoM“
.teertS eltryM no esuoh wolley eno ylno saw ereht ,yletanutroF .sserdda s’ylimE nettogrof dah taht tliug fo egnit a htiw dezilaer yaR  .seno devol desaeced morf stfig thguorb eh nehw doog kool ot dekil eh dna
.mih ekatrevo ot denetaerht peels fo sbewboc ,taes nrow llew eht ni kcab tas eH
.dellac rehtom siH ”!ybab ,yaR“
”?ni flesym tel ll’I sseuG“
.gnir ot nageb enohp sih ,rac sih ot kcab dedaeh yaR sA
,rekrad saw gniht sihT .krad saw esuoh
.ecnatsid eht ni thgil fo tnilg tfos eht fo thgis thguac yaR ,nehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,denwo eh tiftuo tsecin eht saw ti
”,hcum yrev uoy devol ehS“
.emahs ot sevael eht tup taht ssengums a htiw hctaw eht gnihsidnarb ,deralced eh
,slraep eht psarg ot mih rof hguone tsuj moor eht detanimulli tI
.ekirts ot gniraperp ,nori eht detfil eH
.lley detartsurf a ekil dednuos tahw tuo tel gniht eht ,mih dniheB
.elbuort lautirips saw ereht reverehw nwot eht dnuora nward flesmih dnuof eh ,pohs drocer lacol eht ta stfihs neewteB
.flesti ereht ti detnalp dah rorrim eht ni gniht eht fi sa ,peels sih ni mih ot emoc dah aedi ehT
”,pu uoy ekow I yrros m’I“ ”.derit tsuJ“
.depsag ehs ”!on hO“
mrof yltsohg ’siroD
tub leef t’ndluoc ylimE taht eno
.reh ot tuo meht dleh dna tekcop taoc sih fo tuo slraep eht dellup eH
.em rof od nac uoy gniht eno si ereht oS“
.rac eht detrats eH
”,traehteews uoy knaht ,hO“  .detnurg eh
.ereh fo tuo lleh eht teg ot dedeen eh nehw ereht eb llits dluow rorrim eht yllufepoH
”,edart ot gnihtemos thguorb I“
.ruf daeh delruc reh ni wob a dna sserd liatkcoc a gniraew
ytic dlo na ni devil eh ecnis
”.eseht evah ot uoy detnaw ehs taht noitnetta ym ot emac ti tub
.od uoy fi enola uoy evael ot esufer yeht dna meht ta gnikool er’uoy nehw wonk yeht taht ni seeyolpme ksoik llam ekil era stiripS
,ti deraen sa desiar selkcah siH
,taht ekil d’I“
”?raed ,deen uoy od tahW“
.detaicerppa eb d’yeht depoh yllaer eH
,meti tsal eht dehcaer yaR litnu t’nsaw tI
ll’I“ ”.esuoh wolley eht ,teertS eltryM 2125 ta sevil ehS .ylimE rethguad ym ot meht evig dna meht dnif ot uoy tnaw I
.esuoh noitcua eht otni repeed esaenu fo esnes gniworg sih dewollof neht
.ylteiuq dias ylimE ”,uoy knahT“
.rorrim eht ekil tsuj
.tuo dellac eciov s’namow a ”!dnoces a tsuJ“
”.uoy fo duorp s’ehs taht wonk ot uoy detnaw ehS“ .dias yaR
.tekcaj rehtael sih fo slepal eht tuo denethgiarts eH
.delims eh dna mih ot emac aedi wen A .doog
,hcuoc gnitniaf dlo na
.ti htaeneb tuo evag ,ylbamuserp ,doow eht sa rednuht ekil kcarc a saw erehT
ev’I dnA“ .dias yaR ”,neeb reven ev’I“
,stnemom wef a rof yldnilb gninnur retfA
.mih dednuorrus sdoow ehT
.wenk ehs ,deil eh ”,oN“
seldnac emihc etihw wef a htiw demra
.gnirahs t’nerew yeht dah yeht fi tub
.relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,puoL kcaZ yb ”ssalG gnikooL eht wercS“ saw sihT
”.slraep eht em eviG“
.edis eht ot ffo erehwemos derettalc dna psarg sih fo eerf deppils thgilhsalf eht ,did eh sA
er’yehT .esoht lles mih tel t’nod tub ,esle gnihtyna tuoba erac t’nod I
.slraep eht erew
.semalf yb derramnu ,serusaert ytsud htiw derettil yletulosba saw rolrap eht fo roolf ehT
.hguoht ,tey toN  .draeh d’eh
”,ma’am em gnillac potS“  .dias yaR
.dias namow eht ”,ym hO“  .dias yaR
”,ti fo draeh ev’I ,seY“  .dias yaR
moor egarots eht otni kcab derednaw yaR
.srehturd sih evah ton dluow eH
.erofeb stirips live deretnuocne dah eH .cinomed-
.rorrim eht hguorht deppets dna
.slraep eht dnuora delruc yllanif sregnif s’yaR
.dias ehs ”,retteb s’tahT“
.eil etihw elttil sih hguorht nees d’ehs wonk ot dessarrabme tib a ,dias eh ”,mom ,thgirla s’tI“ ”.syad eseht ysub er’uoy wonk I“
sevooh evissam s’tsaeb eht fo eno erofeb tsuj yaw eht fo tuo llor ot mih rof neht dna
,toor dehctertstuo na no thguac gel sih ,ylnedduS
.niaga dekeirhs tsaeb eht ,mih dniheB
.dias yaR ”,siroD ,thgirlA“ ”.siroD
,emoclew gnitsugsid fo dnik a sa taht gnikaT
.mih rof dehcaer hcihw sehcnarb lateleks eht detanimulli ylerab
,emoh pirt sih denekrad tnemaciderp sih gnittifeb sseniree nA
.ruf kcen sih gnilffur tsaeb eht fo htaerb dloc eht tlef eH
.revo nrut ot gnisufer ,tsetorp ni denaorg nogaw noitats ehT
.klaw ot nageb eH
.decirp eb ot detiaw smeti elbarised ssel erehw
gniniar llits dna krad teg ot gnitrats tsuj saw tI
.hsa ot nwod nrub emarf eht dehctaw eh sa
.revlis ot cigrella eb dluow gniht siht nwonk ev'dluohS
,ta kcits a hctef dluoc eh naht sehctaw erom dah eh tub ,hctaw roop eht tsniaga gnihtyna dah eh taht toN .od dluow tahT .hctaw tekcop revlis a tuo dellup dna resserd sih ni reward knuj eht hguorht delfir eH
.revlis devol stirips tsom ,esnefed s'yaR nI
.ni teg ot stpmetta gnittiwnu sih gniyojne eb ot demees sevael gums ehT
”.yecarG .rM ,hcum os uoy knahT“
rieht rof ydaer ,edisni desiop tas slraep ehT .topkcaJ
.depleh d’eh stirips morf sknaht fo snekot elttil
.rorrim a fo edisni bmilc ot desoppus saw eh yltcaxe woh tuo erugif ot gniyrt ,htaerb peed a koot eH   .erows yaR
.egatnavdasid eht etiuq ta saw yaR
.gniraelc a ot emac eh ,yllaniF
”?ereh gniod I ma tahw tuB“ .dias ydal eht
.dias ehs ”,esruoc fO“ ”?pleh eht rof nruter ni rovaf a uoy ksa I nac ,yeh tuB .yllaeR“
.daetsni enitocin fo tih a dna tser a rof gniggeb
.gnitae erofeb stsohg ylkcis rof aera na gnikcehc fo tibah eht ni tog ylkciuq d’eH
.dias eh ”,yaR si eman yM“
.ti no gnipeels morf ffits saw liat siH
,etihw dna yffulf saw ehS
.erahs ot desufer dna anut fo nac a denepo dah enoemos fi sa dekool ehS
”.niar ot tuoba s’tI .tnuah ot ecalp tnereffid a kcip ot tnaw yam uoy ,won rof tuB“ .dias eh
,nehctik eht drawot kcab denrut eh sA
,reh dniheb gniregnil siroD deciton yaR ,rediw rood eht denepo ehs sA ”?woH
. .edisni ti thguorb
.eert tseilgu s’dlrow eht no
”.ynnep a flah rof ti lles t’nac I .ti ekaT
.stcefed suoivbo s’emoh eht gnirevoc
.gninrom taht ssenthgirb gnidnilb eht ot tsartnoc hsrah a
.esnesnon daed gnieb siht ot desu teg dluoc I eveileb od I “
;erofeb sraey net morp ot nrow d’eh tius eht ni desserd saw eH
,resserd sih evoba rorrim dekcarc eht ni yllacitegolopa flesmih ta dekool eH  .ton did tI
”,uoy rehtob ot yrros m’I“ ”?pu s’tahW“
”,ereh yllaer t’nera slraep ruoY“
.leef t’ndluoc yaR ezeerb a ni gnigniws ssom
.roines sih edaced a revo nogaw noitats kcalb pu taeb a ,rac sih ot tuo dedaeh dna elbat eht ffo syek sih debbarg eH
.deraeppaer t’ndah gniht ywodahs ehT .hcliZ
.prahs oot raf dna egral oot raf erew hteet sti tub
.draeh t’ndah mom sih depoh dna denaorg yaR
.seye s’yaR erofeb yltneg detfihs mrof reH
.ees reven d’yeht noitcua na ta tubed
”,enif m’I“ .deksa mom sih
.krad eht dnim t’ndid ylekil ti seye on dah ti ecnis dna ,rorrim eht rof kcab daeh dluow eh wenk ylerus tsaeb ehT  .epacse sti delangis senob nekorb ekil gnikcarc doow fo dnuos ehT
.ssensuoicsnoc sih otni de-ognadnaf "ydospahR naimehoB" .yadot toN
,ffuh a htiw deb fo tuo dellor eH .dias eh
”,ma’am ,yrros m’I“  .dias namow eht
.ruf sih elffur ot tuo gnillips ssalg eht dniheb morf dniw dloc eht
”-nam gnuoy ,syawynA
,rethgil sih tuo dellup eH
,etteragic sih fo ttub eht deppord eH
.rorrim eht deklats dna nori erif ssarb euqitna na debbarg eH
.kcab slraep esoht teg reven d’eh ,ti elots ro revo ti dekconk pup etaredisnocni emos fI
.flesmih thgir ot noitcart hguone niag ot gnilggurts
.sih saw ssa s’rorrim tahT
.gnol woh swonk dog rof potsnon gnimaercs neeb d’eh taht dezilaer eh
.sdeew eht ni tuo ssap neht dna pu worht ot egru gnimlehwrevo sih etipsed drawrof mih yrrac ot hguone sgel sih detavitom emoh fo thgis ehT
.demaets dna delbbub niks sti sa hctaw eht gnippord
.yresim sih ffo egde eht ekat ot depleh enitocin eht sa gnilruc seot sih ,llup peed a koot eH .etteragic gninrom a dah yaR ,pu ekaw ot eeffoc gninrom a dah elpoep emoS
.yldas delims yaR
.moor eht fo kcab eht ni lenitnes a ekil doots rorrim dlo ehT
.sreh etisoppo riahc eht ni nwod gnittis ,detsisni eh
.enola edisni ffuts taht lla luah ot reh evael ot gniog t’nsaw eh ,timmad dna ,mom sih devol eh tuB
.trid eht otni dehsams tuons sih sa lluks sih hguorht detaidar niaP
.tnatropmi neeb evah tsum ti ,ylrae siht mih gnillac ton tuoba doog yllausu saw ehS .”moM“
.gnireffo sih htiw nehctik eht otni kcab dehcram eH .hctaw ,yrroS
.emarf nedoow derrahc eht otno elttob lluf eht depmud neht
.erofeb thgin eht morf sehtolc sih ni desserd llits
.roolf etercnoc eht no derettalc hcihw nori eht pord ot mih gnicrof dna mra sih otni gniggid swalc
tsuj thgilhsalf sih litnu deklaw eh sa rekrad dna rekrad ylidaets werg tI
.evisserppo saw ygrene ehT
tcejbo desruc a dnif d’eh ,yllanoisaccO
.namow yltsohg eht ediseb hcuoc eht no nwod tas yaR
etteragic denrae-llew a gnikoms
feiht eht dnif saw od ot dah eh lla ,woN
.enohp sih rof delbmuf eh sa roolf eht ot derettalc hcihw selttob reeb tfarc ytpme wef a edisa dehsup eH
”,etunim a ni revo eb ll’I ,haeY“
.ees yldrah dluoc yaR ,thgilhsalf sih tuohtiW
”.ma’am ,yrros m’I“ .dias eh
.eson dna srae reh no stniop nworb eht morf edisa rehtom reh fo egami gnittips eht tsomla
.sgnileef reh gnitruh ksir naht tramlaW ruoh-42 a ni tsol thgiarts sruoh enin-ytneves rof ekawa yats rehtar d’eh tub ,elbissop sa noos sa emoh teg ot dekil evah dluow ,tcaf ni ,eH  .dias eh ”,mom
gnikniht derebmemer eH
.hcrop eht otno tuo debmilc ti sa thgiew sti htaeneb ylbidua denaorg doow ehT
.sbuc aneyh fo elkcac a ekil dehgual yltnelis yeht ”,ahaH“
.ti htrow saw elims etaciled s’ylimE tub
”?I ma erehw ,nam gnuoY“
”?moor kcab eht ni rorrim dlo taht evah I naC“
.tcafitra yloh a erew yeht fi sa meht gnidloh
.rac sih fo knurt eht otni rorrim-ton elbirroh eht gniffuts saw yaR ,retal ruoh nA
.deneppah gnihtoN
,nehctik eht ot denruter eH
.tnemom yna tuons sih ni rood eht mals ot deraperp demees ehS  .deksa ehs ”?seY“
.enog saw ehs ,nehT
,efil ot derettups rac eht dna niaga yek eht denrut yaR
.ees dluoc ti wenk yaR tub
.enod neeb ydaerla dah egamad eht dezilaer neht
.esproc hserf a fo htaerb eht ekil
eh nehT .rennid etal ylemertxe na ekil erom saw
dah eH ?ton yhW  .edart A
.seert eht hguorht htap eht dewollof eh sa swap sih htaeneb dehcnurc sevael ehT
.ylkciuq ti detcarter eH
.reilf eht pu til dna
,yltnatiseh ,dna knurt sih morf rorrim eht detfeh eh ,emoh tog eh ecnO
.kcen reh dnuora slraep tnagele htiw sserd tevlev gnol a ni tac etihw yffulf a ,hcuoc eht no
.deltsirb ylsuoucipsnoc llits ,eciffo eht ot revo deirruh eH
.aesuan fo sevaw kcab gnithgif dna gnitfil yvaeh fo rulb a erew setunim wef txen ehT
.elzzird dipet a ot deteiuq dah niar eht tub ,won gob wollahs a fo erom saw yawevird ehT
.edisni mih gninokceb
thgilhsalf eht no dekcilc eh nehT
”.deen uoy gnihtemos tog ev’I .em hsams t’nac uoY“
,ria ytsum ,looc fo htaerb retfa htaerb koot eh sa detsetorp sgnul siH
”?won sneppah tahW .hO“
,mih ta dehcnual dna seert eht hguorht detlob rulb kcalb A
.sseniloh eht detagen retaw yloh gnilaets fi ylfeirb derednow eH
.dlrow rorrim eht edisni rekrad gnitteg saw tI
.eciffo eht otni kcab tnew ehs sa dias mom sih ”,traehteews yakO“
.ecalkcen eht rof gnikool ,dnuorg eht ta yletarepsed dewalc dna no dednal d’eh eenk eht ni niap eht derongi eH
.edistuo mih rof gnitiaw saw mom sih was dna
.daed saw ehs ,lla retfA
”,setunim neetfif ni ereht eb ll’I“
.trihs dnab etirovaf sih gniniats ,eson sih morf spil sih nwod gninnur doolb tlef eH
.ssenippah htiw gniwolg yllaretil
.sdoow krad eht hguorht nar eh sa ylteiuq erows daetsni dna ,tnedurp erom saw teiuq dediced eH
.dias yaR ”,esaelp ,seY“
.kcab sih ni knik eht tuo krow pleh dluow taht gniod fi sa ,tnemom a rof ti deggaw eH
?mih gnikcom yeht ereW .ylgums deimmihs ssalg eht dnoyeb sevael tilnoom ehT
.ssarg eht otni gnilbmut mih gnidnes ,delf eh sa mih rednu yaw evag sriats delaocrahc ehT
.kool suoicilam ylgnihtees a mih evag tsaeb ehT
.flehs eht ffo gnilbmut laerec fo sexob wef a tnes dna llaw derepap ylikcat eht otni drah demmals eH
.eson evitisnes sih elknirc mih edam
,peed a koot  dna etteragic a til eH .knis sih evoba tenibac eht morf thgilhsalf a debbarg eH .thgil a tuohtiw ni gniog t’nsaw eh ,ni gniog saw eh fI
.semit eerht doow eht tsniaga rekconk eht deppar dna rood tnorf eht dehcaorppa eH
.seert erew mih dnuora sbolb krad eht llet dluoc eh taht ni
.rorrim gnikcuf a saw ti esruoc fO .rorrim A
.xob yrlewej tevlev a revo dehsurb sregnif siH
.sexob eht hguorht gniggid nageb eH
.ffiuq deroloc-tsur esool a otni swalc sih htiw kcab ruf daeh sih gnibmoc
.ecnaraeppa rehtona edam t’ndah feiht eht tub ,ereht ni og ot tnaw t’ndid yllaer ,yllaer eH
s’yaR naht reggib erew teef nevolc sti dna
.nwod wols ot nageb eh dna mih deyarteb sgel siH
.teerts eht nwod lardehtac eht morf nelots d’eh taht
”,eseht ekat annog tsuj m’I“
”.taht xif llew sa yam I
.peels ot kcab mih llul niar eht tel dna emoh og dluoc eh os htiw revo siht gnitteg ot drawrof gnikool saw yaR
.rehtegot lla spihc hsif fo elttek tnereffid a erew stirips livE
.”ffo dessip“ ot ”tuo depeerc“ morf hctiws a deppilf d’eh ,tniop emos tA
.tsrow eht erew sliob ehT
,dik a saw eh nehW
,elat eht llet ot devil dna siht ekil gnihtemos decneirepxe dah reve fo yrotsih eht ni enoyna fi ees ot tenretni eht deruocs eH
,puoL kcaZ yb seires cimoc pmopohcysP gniogno eht ot noitcudortni na si yrots sihT
.won retteb wenk eH
,retal reeb fo esac a flah dna ,setteragic fo kcap a ,sruoh lareveS
.rewsna na ot resolc erehwon saw eh
,swodniw on erew ereht ecnis ereht kcab lleh sa krad saw tI
.gniltsirb ruf etihw reh ,dias siroD
.hguone noos taht xif d’yeht ekil dekool ecnatsid eht ni sduolc krad eht tub
”.edistuo gnihtyreve evael ot tnaw t’nod I dna
.hguorht enog d’eh eno eht ekil yltcaxe dekool taht rorrim a morf mih ta kcab detcelfer nehctik sih was dna mih dniheb dekool eH
.llaf eht ni slraep eht tsol d’eH
,rorrim eht morf revotfel ssalg nekorb eht yrub ot drayhcruhc eht ot pirt ruoh gnihctiw a
…neht dna ,pan yad-dim dnoces ym ekat ot nwod dial I“ .deksa ehs
,hceercs elbirroh a evag tI .yltneg ylgnisirprus hctaw eht depsarg walc delrang suomrone s’tI
.tsal sih sa tuoba kniht ot ton deirt eh hcihw gard wols
”.slraep ym sah ehs wonk I litnu tser t’now I .gnitiaw eb ll’I“ .dias siroD ”,neht
eht fo edisni ehT  .taht rof deraperp yllaer t’nsaw llits eh tub ,tihs fo tol a nees d’eH
tlef eH .tnemom a rof daeh sih dnuora maws neve ”doog“ drow ehT
,rorrim eht otni thgir gnillorts yllausac deirt d’eh ,tsriF
”,pan taht morf pu ekaw t’ndid uoy …hu uoY“
hcihw eriF yldneirF dellac levon htgnel lluf a no gnikrow yltnerruc s’eh ,gnitirw s’kcaZ deyojne uoy fI
,taoc sih fo kcab eht ssorca deggard swalc s’gniht ehT
.smota yb ruf sih gnissim
.tuo flesmih koohs neht ,dehcterts
.knurd elttil a llits ylbissop ,revognuh yletinifed saw eH
.rood hcrop ysmilf sih nepo dekcik yaR   .eid
”,ylimE ,emoclew yrev er’uoY“
.ylper ni delrans eH
.pan a dedeen eh dna won noon saw tI
,esuoh eht fo edistuo rethgirb yllanigram ylno saw tI
.slraep nmad eht dnuof eh ecno taht rof kool ot evah d’eH .tcejbo detnuah
.lward gnimrahc reh ni deksa mom sih
.dnuora gniwercs rof doom eht ni ton ,dias yaR
.yawevird etercnoc eht no derettahs ssalg ehT
.luos sih fo tramlaW ruoh-42 eht retne ot tuoba saw eh dezilaer eh taht
roced ykriuq dna stnalp gnignah fo stol htiw
.mih erofeb saw gniht eht retal tnemom a dna ,mih htaeneb tfihs
.tiaw ot evah dluow tI ”!ydaer s’aeT“
.rorrim eht ni tserof eht otni kcab detaerter dna
”.tuo gnikrow saw rorrim wen eht woh ees ot detnaw tsuj I ,ybab yeH“
dnuorg eht tlef eH
.ruf sih morf trid dna ,doolb ,hsa eht evomer ot rewohs gninrom-dim a dna
,did ehs sa tpecxe ;kcen reh no slraep eht ta gnipsalc ,dias ehs ”,eseht ekaT
.stros fo retnuh tsohg a emoceb d’eH
.detnarrawnu t’nsaw ssertsid reH
.dluoc eh nehw tuo meht pleh ot ytud tnelis sih ti edam dah yaR dna ,meht ot dehcatta stseug gnittiwnu htiw smeti fo noissessop otni emac yltneuqerf esuoh noitcua ehT
”,ti llac ot tnaw uoy revetahw ro
.yzarc saw eh kniht yeht tsel ,eromyna sklof ot ti noitnem ot ton denrael eh taht saw
.dnuorg eht ot delbmut eh dna
ot dah rorrim eht ,tsriF
,ereh m’I fi ,lleW“
.no evom stirips depleh tsuj eh emit eht fo tsoM
.tnrub neeb dah doow eht fi sa kcalb saw emarf nedoow stI
.noisnam eht fo tuo nar dna teef sih ot kcab delbmarcs eH
.enohp eht pu gnikcip ,dias eh ”,mom ,yeH“
.nwod denrub dah esuoh eht retfa litnu ffuts gnitcelloc detrats t’ndah gniht ywodahs eht ,ylraelC
.krow gnidrawer saw ti tub ,diap taht boj a t’nsaw tI
.ruf kcen sih gnilkcirp ,mih delggin gnihtemos ,did eh sA
,ssalg eht morf welb dniw dloc A
.emahs ot ,hcruhC tsitpaB truocraH fo tiplup eht ta noil dlo eht ,nosnhoJ dereveR tup ev’dluow ti duol os foor nit eht tsniaga deraor niar eht dna
.peels ot kcab mih llul niar eht fo rettap rettip ydaets eht tel dna ,kcap eht ffo gnihsinif ,reeb rehtona delzzug eH .ylbaborP .pu ekow eh nehw ereht eb llits dluow rorrim ehT
.ytiniffAruF dna snootbeW htob no daer nac uoy hcihw
.pu ekow eh erofeb sruoh ruof rehtona tsael ta eb dluow ti ,srehturd sih dah eh fI
.ylsuovren tekcop taoc sih ni slraep eht revo decart sregnif siH
mih rof gnipsarg yldnilb fi sa dnuora gnippihw
.yaR thguoht ,nmad ,hA  .hself
.ti htiw enod neeb dna gniht nmad eht deppord ydaerla evah d’eh ,slraep eht rethguad reh gnirb d’eh siroD desimorp ydaerla t’ndah eh fI
,hcrop eht no tas yaR
retaw yloh htiw dellif elttob retaw citsalp a dna
.noertaP sih no daer nac uoy
.edistuo ti gnivael ksir t’ndluoc eh tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.enod d’eh tahw deretsiger eh sa mih koot cinaP
evol I“ .dias ehs
.trap siht detah eH
.nehctik detsefni hcaor ,gnitsugsid sih fo thgil wolley ygnid eht saw tI
pu nworg d’eh sa degnahc dah taht gniht ylno ehT .efil elohw sih meht ees ot elba neeb d’eh
.tip dum gnirettalps a otni yawevird eht gninrut erofeb
enotgnir sih gnos etirovaf sih gnikam taht
.tuons eht no pmub lufniap a saw nettog d’eh lla tub
mih detten hcihw ,retaw yloh ni ti desuod eh ,nehT
.erofeb sruoh dne eht dehcaer gnivah eldeen eht
.sdratsab ykaens eb dluoc stiripS .dah ti spahreP
?erehW !slraep s’rehtoM“
?uoy rof od nac I gnihtyna ereht sI“
cihc ybbahs fo tros saw ti won tub ,wolagnub ecin yrev a neeb ecno dah ti ekil dekool tI
,won dezilaer yaR ,os dnA .enog saw tI
mih sdrawot ksed eht ssorca gum sih dils ehs sa kniw a htiw dias ehs
”,slraep eht rof edart ot gnihtemos tog ev’I ,thgirlA“
.edistuo ti delruh dna
,taht dekil sdoG .gnihtemos ro meht rof esnecni emos nrub ot evah d’eH