nerdlihc ruo lla roF
.yawa nevig neeb d’ehs retfa reh ot kcab thguorb saw spup reh fo enO
.lrig ym ,nwod yaw ruoy nO“
.seitilibarenluv on dah taht ned a ekiL .ytefas
.erofeb dah ehs naht rehtruf knis flesreh tlef ehs dna
.erofeb roloc a hcus nees reven d’ehS
,sgod eht rof tsuj aera na ffo noitces ot tif nees dah stnerap s'yob eht
na eicarG dellac semitemos yob reh hguohT
.tey seye sih nepo neve t’ndluoc eH
.ssuf a esuac t’ndluow eicarG taht thgin ta hguone etal saw ti wenk ehs tub ,god rehto eht ffo seye reh gnikat ekil t’ndid ehS
regnif tsellams reh fo lian derucinam llew ,gnol ehT
.peels luftser a otni gnillaf morf reh detneverp
?tnatropmI ?laiceps
.rae sih gnikcil yb mih ekaw ot
pu dehcaer ssetnaig ehT
…leef reh edam ti
srats gnirettilg dna revlis fo skaerts htiw deremmihs taht kcalb fo seboR
”?ereh evah ew od ohw woN“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.moor eht nethgirb ot thgilnoom fo stnuoma elpma dewolla
tsoob a s’pup eht gnivig
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
esnopser ni elbmurg dna
.pmub llams a tlef ehs litnU
.gnimoob tlef evah dluohs tI
egdelwonk drocer ot ekil I
.mih dniheb rood eht desolc eh elihw
dne na ot emac gnos reh nehW
.mroftalp eht ffo reh gnitfil dna
.tsol evah uoy tahw dna deniag evah uoy tahw em htiw erahS
.dnuos taht ot esnopser ni krab yhctarcs ,truc a evag ehS
.ma I ohw wonk uoy hO“
.ssenisub reh fo yna t’nsaw yllaer taht esnesnon neeb dah ti fo tol A
.erom ecno said eht no wedyenoH gnicalp ,ekops ehS
.yltcaxe yhw aedi on dah ehS
.eulb mraw tfos a nrut dna
.trap tsom eht rof ,teiuq saw ni devil yeht ned evissam ehT
.yks tilrats eht rednu sneppah taht gnihtyreve tsom ees I“
.daed saw ehs wenk wedyenoH
,god llams a gniniatnoc ,esolc gnuh tI
smra sih otni pup eht gnitfil yob A
.segami tpurba trohs nI
tsitra ,yrruf ,yag a si ohw
,elpoep ylredle reh gnikaw ekil t’ndid gup ehT
.trohs saw sraey 41 ebyam
”.sevaw eht woleb peed
niaga sgel tnorf reh fo stip eht rednu emac sdnah egraL
.erom yna gnisir eb ot mees t’ndid tI
.sdnuos namuh tseb eht ylbaborp erew esohT
,llams saw yrotirret rieht hguohT
,reh ta daeh sih detlit eH
.emit siht ta seno tnatropmi eht t’nerew esoht tuB
.niaga efil reh fo segami htiw gnihsalf saw ti wenk ehs tub ti ees t’ndluoc ehs
.hsalf a tsuJ .gnihtemos was ehs
devol dah taht sgnieb eht ot tnatsni na ekil tlef tahw ni enog dna emoc dah efil reh tahT
.enog saw ti neht dnA
pup siht gnirewohS .yob reH
said eht fo ecafrus yretaw eht no kcab reh decalp tnaig eht nehw tnemom a rof dekcinap eninac ehT
,yzzuF eht amotI yb
.xyno dna htmraw ni reh gnilddaws
”sratS fo aeS A“ saw sihT
,reh woleb mroftalp eht htiw detanoser llac dehctip hgih reH .delwoh dna
efil retfa eht fo tnerruc eht gnola dewolf ohw esoht gnissim meht fo tsom
.htaerb reh desaeler ehs nehT
,sladnas dlo fo riap a otni teef sih deppils eH
htaerb peed a koot ehs tuB
,kcab reh no hctarcs a reh evag ylregnig
.snoitom eht hguorht og ot ecin tlef ti tub
.eciov reh dnif ot tnemom a reh koot tI .did wedyenoH oS
.yllufthguoht daeh reh detlit ssetnaig ehT
”.em rof llew meht hsiw
?lrig ybab pu s’tahW“
woleb roolf looc eht ot reh derewol ylregnig dna
.eroc eht ot reh koohs evah dluohs tI
yzzuF eht amotI yb
,yzzuF eht amotI yb ”sratS fo aeS A“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
rood kcab eht ta pets ddo eht revo gnipael erofeb mih retfa delddot ehs os
.selprup dna seulb fo yarra na deremmihs tub
.srats ynam eht ekil gniremmihs
.daetsni taert a evah ereh ,taht tae t'nod ,oN .tiS .revo lloR
,drawrof lessev reh depmub dna
.woleb hself eht gnilooc
,sgnidnuorrus reh ni gnikaT
?trohs saw sraey 41 tuoba tahW ?trohS
enihw gnitrofmoc a mih evag ehS
.trohs rof dna gnol rof
.sevlesmeht rof edam dah stnerap s’yob reh ned eht naht rellat doots ylisae ehS
”?eno elttil em rof kaeps ,lleW“
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.reh rof derac dna
,trid dna tsud gnillemS
.reh ediseb gnola dewolf ohw esoht htiw smaerd gnirahs semitemoS
?saw taht tahw wonk ehs did yhW ?elprup
dellac dah yob reh tahw fo tnih tniaf a
tsol eb ton nac yeht
.neeb dah taht tahw
,yawyrtne na ta gnidnats namow llat a deciton ehs
.mih ot yltfos gnignis dna
.elims reh ni detnilg taht seninac ylraep gnol eht rof evas namuH
.efas erom tlef reven d’ehs rehtona no tub
sroloc dna sepahs esoht was ehs namow eht ta pu kcab gnikooL
.moor eht hguorht detarebrever dlrow eht naht reggib demees taht eciov A
.niaga dekrab wedyenoH
.saw ehs demussa ehs tsael ta rO
,redloc tib elttil a tlef senob reh ni llihc ehT .mlac tub
.reh desiar ohw namow eht fo gnas ehS
.meht ot kaeuqs thgir eht tsuj dah taht syot dna sdoof ytsat
.nwo reh fo senifnoc eht hguorht dluoc ehs sa hcum sa lessev sih tuoba deffins ehS
,lwoc reh fo sgnirevoc eht dniheb
.nedrag eht fo htrae eht ta dekrow rehtaf sih elihw
,resolc lessev reh degru wedyenoH  .poleved ot esnes taht rof detrats yenruoj sih retfa elihw a rof eb t’ndluow ti derugif ehs hguohT
.tsrif dray eht fo noitces ”god“ eht ni ssenisub rieht enod d’yeht retfa ylno tub
,evoba morf dellac ssetnaig ehT
.worros fo gnas ehS
derugif ehs tub ecalp siht fo weiv eht naht retteb era smaerd ehT
.hcrop eht otno dna
.reh revo hsaw mlac tlef ehs tuB
.yob namuh reh dna reh fo thgis eht ta deffuh dna
sdnuos esoht thguoht ehs taht ecnerrucco hguone raluger htiw ”hctib etulosba“
.gnineppah saw tahw dootsrednu ehs woh erus t’nsaw ehS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ksat llams siht ot ees osla I tuB“
.nwo reh fo smaerd lufecaep fo
.golatac dluoc god eno yna naht sllems erom raf htiw dellif dlrow a fO
”.uoy dednuorrus taht evol eht dna
.spets eht no nwod flesmih gnittis
.ytisoiruc htiw gaw liat reh gnileef
doof reh eta ehs erehw tops eht dekoolrevo taht swodniw daorB
,sladnas esoht dekil ehs
,ylderit ereht gnidnats
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,woleb morf pu dehsur thgil fo serehps ,reh dnuorA
ssentaerg eht neviG
.won trats ot nosaer on was ehs dna ,tuoba denrecnoc saw ro fo wenk ehs gniht a neeb yllaer reven dah emiT
,retaw ekil remmihs ot mroftalp eht fo ecafrus eht gnisuac devaw yltneg dnah rehto
.daed ylniatrec tsom saw
si yrots s’yadoT dna
deb eht ni pu gnittis erofeb ,denihw dah eh
.thguoht yllaitini dah wedyenoH naht rellat raf saw ehs taht gnilaever drawrof yaw reh edam dna sniatruc eht hguorht deppets namow ehT
,tnemevom reh htiw derettulf
.tas wedyenoH hcihw nopu mroftalp eht fo egde eht pirg ot gnimoc yltneg
a tahw eulc on dah wedyenoH
.seiruxul elttil eht fo gnas ehS
,reh eciton neve dluow egral os gnieb a taht deifirret neeb evah dluohs ehs
…ta tser rieht dedeen yeht
.skrab cificeps ylhgih ,ynam oot tsuj erew ereht ;yllaer reh no tsol erew sdnuos namuh tsoM
.retsum dluoc eh evol eht lla htiw
sgel tnorf reh fo stip eht rednu dekooh sdnah egral sih
deb eht no revo delffuhs ehs tub ,denaorg senob elucsinim reH
,enot enirahccas taht desu eh nehw ekil syawla did ehS  ”?yttop ot deen uoY
s’namow ehT ”.tser ot seye ym esolc I emos rof hguohT
,ecaf reh nopu tas tnecserc a fo epahs eht ksam A
,sdeb mraw htiw ecalp A
.ni pup reh dna reh gnikat yob eht dna reh gniworg tuo nwonk dah ehs ylimaf ehT
.sthgin tsom em ees uoY
”,ssenisub ruoy oD .weD ,no oG“
taht os meht drocer I dna ,lautcaf dna suoititcif ,seirots ruoy fO
wonk ylbaborp dluohs ehs
,lausu rep sa ylduol gnirons ,rekaterac reh saw ohw yob namuh ehT
,tfel wehc ot hcihw htiw hteet fo tol a evah t’ndid wedyenoH .tfos dna ecin saw erutxet eht dna
nrut ni yob eht ta yltnatcepxe dekool dna spets eht fo pot eht ta tas ehs
,reverof ekil tlef tahw rof tnerruc eht gnola detfird ehS
”sratS fo aeS A“   yojne esaelP
.seye reh ot emoc evah dluow sraet
.pal sih otni fles rellams reh gnitfihs dna
,niaga ecafrus eht dehcuot namow ehT ”.peels uoy elihw
”,tser fo stol teg uoy taht si
yad lla nus eht ni tuo tis ot tog yeht esuac
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.nwod wedyenoH deirrac yltneg taht
,tfos saw tI .t’ndid ti tuB
,seye reh gnirucsbo
htolc etihw a ni
”.emit sih s’ti nehw
,rehtom sih dna yob eht gnilaever etihw citats eht yawa gnitlem selppir eht
.yob taht rof yrrow ton oD“
.enihw denrecnoc a evag wedyenoH  ”?ydaer uoy erA“
.ksam reh nopu detcarfer
derobal t’nsaw ti ,dewols
.god rehtonA .ylimaf llams A
.hcaer reven dluoc tub
”,elbirret si htaerb ruoy …weD…hcelb “  .emas eht lla dnamed reh ta ekowa tub
,ruf reh erongi ot demees ezeerb eht
.thgin eht fo elddim eht ni pu gnikaw derebmemer ehS
.yniturcs reh rednu delggirw eh dna
reh htiw neeb dah ohw esoht ot gninaem dleh efil reh gniwonK .evol gnas ehS
,god llams eht dnuora cirbaf eht evow ehs
,drawrof emac revlis fo sdnaH
.nrecnoc ni detrotnoc ecaf sih fo ksam kcalb ehT
.mroftalp eht fo og tel
,rood kcab eht ot gnola devom ydaerla dah yob ehT ”?weD“
.srennid ytsat dna staerT
evah ot demees ecafrus ehT
.srae reh gulp t’ndid tI
uoy teg emoc ll’I“
,og sluos lla erehw ecalp taht ot uoy dnes I nehT“
.yrehpirep reh fo renroc eht ni tnemevom deciton dna niaga dekrab ehS
,yks tnatsid eht ni remmilg tniaf a ylno won luos llams ehT
,nwod tlenk dah ehS
,reh ta gnizag saw ehs demussa weD tsael ta rO
.selkna god ynit reh ot pu dehcaer hcihw
.emit reh erofeb gnissap reh ot kcab emoc dah ohw pup eht fO
,meht edam evah dluoc ehs fI
”.efil devil trohs a hcus ni modsiw hcum oS“
derebmemer ehs nehT
.erofeb nees reven d’ehs hcihw fo ynam
”?traeh raed ,dnatsrednu uoy oD“
,denaorg yob eht ”,traehteews og s’tel ,yakooO“
.tsehc dna eson reh ni erusserp yzzuf thgils taht tlef ehs
,meht ekil gnihton dekool eh dna
.llew sa gup eht detius
.eninac ralucitrap taht detius dnuos eht tlef ehs tub saw ”gup“
.edam dah ehs spup ehT
htaerb s’wedyenoH
tuo dna ni gnitfird
hcuoc eht no tops reh no revo dellor gup eht eicarG
edit eht yb delffum eciov
.lessev nwo reh kcurts dah taht eno eht ta pu dekool ehS
dehcti syawla ehs erehw sredluohs reh neewteb thgir
lian elgnis a fo epiws lufecarg a htiW
.ereht dna ereh luos a depmub eno neht dna won tub
,tiaw ot nrut reh saw ti txeN
.dnatsrednu did ehS
dna revlis fo scirbaf yb derucsbo mrof reh
…nedrag eht ni yalp ot dewolla erew yehT
.semoc emit rieht nehw
.luos reh ot mlab a ekil ,gnilooc
.ot teg ot deganam dah yeht ega lacimonortsa revetahw
.reh htaeneb dna erofeb deyalp efil reH
thgin sa kcalb saw hcihw ,ruf gnol yllanoitpecxe reh fo kcol a htrof gnillup
elppir ot ti gnisuac
.sraey ni gnihtyna ta lwoh ylreporp ot deen eht nees t’ndah ehS
”.ssenisub god ruoy od og s'tel ,weD no emoC“
did ehs nehw dnA
.levarg dna trid no ti gniod neht tnereffid yna t’nsaw ssarg eht no ssenisub gnioD
etulosba ekil tlef tahw ni reh decnocsne tI
.saw ”yttop“ dnuos ehT
.sdnop dna sekal ni gnimmiws fO
desoppus dna rekaterac yob reh desiar dah ohw snamuh eht ot kcab thguoht neht weD
.daed ,oN ?gnimaerD
.eson ro elzzum reh retne t’ndid retaw ehT
.llew sa deb eht morf flesmih devomer eh erofeb
.meht dednamed ehs nehw skcans ytsat reh tog taht seno eht
,seno tnatropmi eht wenk ehs ,tuB
peed a gnikat htiw semoc taht gnileef yffuts fo dnik ehT
”,uoy erofeb emac ohw esoht yb dednuorrus
.remaerts hctiwt lanoisacco dna
.yzzufsiamoti@ rettiwt sih no
,ylderit delbmur yob eht
,eno llams ,ecalp suoyoj a fo maerd lliw uoY“
.efil ruoy fo em llet uoY
eno fo mlap eht otni wedyenoH gnipoocs
tlef uoy dlrow eht fO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yako eb dluow gnihtyreve wenk ehs tuB
.dekrab wedyenoH
.reh dniheb gniliart
,uzt hihs dlo raey 41 eht ,wedyenoH
revlis fo edam dnah eno sa niaga moor eht dellif eciov gnihtoos reH
.devil tey ton efil a fo tnatsni nA
.tar lanoisacco eht gnisahC
level emos no thguoht wedyenoH ,ecneserp s’namow siht fo
.daed saw wedyenoH
.cirbaf fo hcterts daorb a otni sevlesmeht devaew yeht dna sessert esoht tuc ehs
,pu kcab gnimoc enoyna ees uoy fI
.yliratnemom drawpu toohs ot ti desuac taht
mrof llams a revo deldduh
?dlihc ,em rof gnis uoy lliw nehT“
ecamirg lacipyt sih evag eH
retaw emoceb yllautca
ecaf s’namow eht no ylthgirb enohs noom eht tub ,krad emaceb moor eht
,sroloc dna sepahs gnignahc roolf eht was ehs nwod ecnalg a htiW
.elims eltneg ni delruc thgilnoom htiw detniap spil sa
.nwod reh gnittes erofeb spets eht nwod reh deirrac dna
.yawrood eht hguorht ni detfird ezeerb remmus looc A .tnatcepxe tub
tnaig a fo sdnah eht
.ecaf ekil-namuh tfos a fo sedis eht dna ,sworb
.aera rehtona ni ssarg dna srewolf eht lla htiw
srats fo naeco na ssorca reh deirrac hcihw elbbub ehT
.eromyna seye reh gninepo rehtob yllausu t’ndid ehS .kcurts neeb dah
.riah ssel tib a dna selknirw fo snoitidda eht evas degnahc ylerab dah yeht tey
dehctiwt eson elttil siH   .spihc nroc
reh htiw pu nworg yllacitcarp dah yob namuh reH
.reh mrah ot ni kaens ot srotaderp rof yaw oN
rovalf fo tol a dah yeht
,yvaeh gnimoceb sdileye reh ,derit gnileef
tnatropmi s’tahw ,enif eb lliw eH
.elahni uoy erofeb tsuj nway
smra reh nopu daeh reh gniyal ,tser a ot emac namow ehT   .did ehs tuB
.eninac llams eht ta nwod dezag ehs sa
.lworg wol a tuo tel eicarG nehw delbmurg yob ehT ”.uoy ,hsuH“
.dlog ni delddaws ,yllaer yppup a
.thgis eht ta dehcnelc dah traeh reh ekil tlef wedyenoH  ”.nac I erehw ti erahs ot dna