nogard a saw yllaer ti erus saw eh erofeb setunim wef a saw tI
,emit siht ylsuoires ,deredisnoc eH
,daehrevo deleehw slluG
daetsni tnuh ot deirt I dna
”?sllug esoht eeS“ ,dias neht
.esiwrehto evac eht ot ti ekam ot elba neeb evah t’ndluow ehs niatrec saw redipS
*** .srehtaef thgilf eht neewteb nwod gniltsen yffulf dah llits ehS
.ylrae llits saw tI
,ria-dim ni hsif sih netae-flah gnivah
”?nogard laer a uoy erA“
.saw eh naht ti ta rekciuq saw ehs setunim nihtiW
.kcalb ylraen sgniw sih
.mih delbuort ti dna
”?ereh yats ew t’nac yhW“
,snogard gnoma gnoleb t’ndid eH
.nogard fo tnecs on saw ereht yhw dezilaer eh taht tsen eht ot emac yeht litnu t’nsaw tI
.sgniw sih dedlof dna ssarg eht ni dednal eh erehw
.sevael ,dnas ,srehtaef llug—
skcor lessum eht ot reh koot redipS
ynoloc ym ot kcab teg ot deen I
,thgin llits rehtona saw tI
,ylnmelos dias ehs ”,likasT“ ”.likasT
uoy naht redlo elttil a saw I nehw ynoloc ruo hguorht emac tI
.yellav elohw eht ni enoyrevE
.gniw s’redipS rednu kcab dekcud esirnuS
”.deid lla yehT“ .dias ehs
,yawa enog evah tsum yehT“
”.ot desu yeht ro“
.deid ehs neht tub
.dias redipS ”?sgniw ruoy hsaw uoy diD“
dewollof esirnuS
,sgniw rieht rednu dniw eht htiW
denruter eh nehW
”.ereht tsomla er’eW“
.dniw fo htaerb a ylecracs
emit gnol yrev a neeb dah tI
.deddon eH .eh did os tuB
.sevoorg eht dellif retaw nehw gnihgual dna
.enarbmem rae s’redipS ot esolc htuom reh tup dna dnuora delggirw ehs
,dniw eht no tsol yltsom eciov reh
”?kcab tnew reven uoY“
,ecnatsid eht ni thgirb os demees dah hcihw
”.woh leef I woN !hO“
,lla ta gniylf eb ot hguone dlo ylerab saw ehS
.ytsur dednuos ti neht dna
.mrala ni mih ta pu dekool ehs woN .peelsa flah
hsif eht fo sniamer eht dehsup esirnuS litnu detiaw eH .dias redipS
.sevaw desahc ekil meht fo daeha taerter ot sworromot erom on—
.nihtiw morf gninihs eb tsum eh thguoht eH
,nwad erofeb ekow redipS
.sehcnarb eht hguorht deltsihw dna deneek dniw ehT
,sgniw reh daerps esirnuS
,wahS .C.K yb ”ykS dna aeS“
,meht gninepo elbuort evah ot reh detcepxe eH
.evac eht otni repeed mih dewollof neht
.tuo kool ot ecnartne evac eht ot tnew dna
,htuom evac eht ni mih raen gniyl neeb dah esirnuS
”.gnol os era sgel ruoy esuaceB“ ”.redipS“
.sehcnuah reh no pu tas dna
.tsaoc eht nwod dna pu dekool redipS .derepsihw ehs
dluohs yeht naht erom dewohs sbir reH
.os yas ot woh wonk t’ndid eh tub
,reh hctaw ot aes eht revo derevoh dna deknab eH
.edit wol ta dnas tew eht ni semag elbmut-dna-hguor gniyalp
,rehtorb sih htiw tnemugra eht derebmemer eH
.meht tae uoY .hsifllehS“
”.uoy ot rehtom a eb nac ohw enoemos deen uoY
.redipS dna esirnuS yb ylesolc dewollof ,htuom evac eht morf delias eltsihT
.yab lessum eht ta egde s’retaw eht ta dednal dna
”?kcis teg I t’ndid yhW
.yawa thgilf ’syad ruof tuoba yellav a ot devom evah ynoloc ym morf srovivrus ehT“
.thguoht d’eh naht neve reitrid dna reiffurcs erew sgniw reH
,syad wef txen eht revo
.elihw a retfa reh deksa eh
.aes eht morf yawa meht deteffub dniw ehT
.dias ehs ”,dloc s’tI“
.htuom evac eht fo egde eht revo depparw swap tnorf reh htiw drawrof gninael
,yab wen a erolpxe dluow yeht yadoT
.yllufnruom mih gnihctaw
,teef gnissap fo snoitareneg morf htooms saw enots ehT
.niar yb dednilb ,nar yehT
yrots sihT .ten.wahsck
.ekawa esirnuS degdun eH
won reh rof ti gniod dnim t’ndid redipS tub
,ti ot gnignilc dnas tew eht denimaxe dna waperof a pu dekcip ehS .dias esirnuS
,tuo saw edit eht evac s’redipS woleb raF
”?eid eh diD“ ”.rehtorb A“
”?ti llik I od woH“
,ylismulc erom hcum
.nwod dehcuorc dna ecnatsid trohs a frus eht otni dedaw esirnuS ”.hsaw ,no oG
”,gniknis era teef yM“
.yawa tnes neeb dah eH
.gninrom taht dah ehs sa hserf sa ylraen demees esirnuS taht desaelp saw eh
.dednal eh sa reh fo tnorf ni hsif eht deppord redipS
.yawdaeh yna ekam ylecracs dluoc esirnuS
.ereht llits saw tsen ehT
.rorroh htiw delkcirp srehtaef gniw s’redipS
.efas dna deretlehs erew yeht evac eht edisni tub
”.slessum nepo ot woh uoy wohs ll’I enod er’uoy nehW“
.su htiw emoc d’uoy hsiw I
.srehtaef reh nethgiarts dna htooms ot nageb dna reh ot resolc devom tub ,dehgis redipS
,seye sih denepo redipS
.yldab siht su gnittih eugalp fo draeh reven ev’I“ .dehgis eltsihT ”.evila
.edis sih ot esolc dedworc dna mih ot txen dednal esirnuS
.aes eht otni delbmurc flah sffilc evoba
.eye reh fo renroc eht fo tuo tae redipS dehctaw dna
,der krad saw nogard egnarts ehT
.peels ot kcab detfird ylraen redipS taht hguone gnol tnelis saw esirnuS ”.oga emit gnol A
.spotffilc tpewsdniw dna yks dna aes fo weiv a ni gniht thgirb ylno eht
.sduolc niar fo roloc eht yks a ni etom der thgirb a sa reh deciton tsrif eH
”?eid lla ynoloc ruoy diD“ ,dias ehs tuB
.pu decnalg eh retal stnemom wef A
.kaeps t’ndid ehs dna snoitseuq rehto yna reh ksa t’ndid eH
.dias redipS ”,hsaW“
meht fo erac ekat depleh I .amam ym neht
.nogard egnarts eht dlot eh ”,ylf reh pleH“
.stnerap sih erew oS
”?hsif rehtona evah I naC“
.seert dewodahs eht gnoma
.yrd llits erew srehtaef ehT
.wahsck ta seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
,yllanif deppots yehT .aes eht ot stnerap sih evig ot hguone gnol deyats dah eh dehsiw redipS
.retlehs hcum evig ot hguone kciht t’nerew seert ehT
,edit wol rof gnitiaw
,niaga emoh elbatrofmoc a dnif reven dluow eh taht
,derehtal dna yppohc saw aes ehT
,wahS .C.K yb ”ykS dna aeS“ saw sihT
doof fo dnik yna rof etiteppa reH
.dias redipS ”,thgif ehT“
saw ehs dna niar htiw ykips erew srehtaef reh
,niaga ega s’esirnuS saw eh tlef redipS
.sffilc eht tsniaga gniraor llits
.noon ta emoh dlo sih ta devirra yehT
.yrd saw tsen eht tub
,delaeuqs dna deppots esirnuS retal tnemom a tub
.ereht eid dluow I os sdoow eht otni tnew I“ ,dias dna
,mih tfil dniw fo tsug a tel dna sgniw sih daerps eH
.gnuoy os eno ton ylniatrec
,denruter eh nehW
”!nogard rehtona s’tI !kooL
”,tfel snogard ylno eht er’eW“
?won evael ot efas s’ti esoppus uoy oD“ ,dias eltsihT
.worromot evael ll’eW“ ,dias redipS
.llew yrev od t’ndid I tub
”.gniniar llits s’tI“ .did esirnuS tub
,dniw eht yb deyoub
toofrednu sirbed tpewsdniw saw ereht tub
.ffilc tseraen eht fo pot eht ot welf eH
,evac sih dehcaer yeht emit eht yB
!nogard rehtona s’tI“
.thginrevo ni nwolb dah taht sduolc htiw etihw saw yks ehT
.meht dniheb tsen eht fo tuo elbmarcs esirnuS draeh eH
,sgniw nwo reh moorg t’ndluoc ehs demialc llits ehS
”?dellac uoy era tahW .uoy knahT“
.neht ,raey a fo retrauq A ”.retniw saw tI“
.reh deksa eh ”?gnorw s’tahW“
.ria hserf rof htuom s’evac eht ot tnew dna pu tog eH
gnitae dehsinif esirnuS
”.thgit dedlof sgniw ruoy peeK“ .dias redipS
koob doog a htiw pu lruc ot uoy gnidnimer
,ylkciuq erom hcum
”?uoy htiw yats I naC“
.gniw s’redipS rednu morf tuo dekeep esirnuS
.deticxe demees ylno esirnuS
,oot kcis tog eh nehT .detnuh yddaD
”?ti gnithgif fo daetsni sgniw rieht rednu og dniw eht tel yeht woh eeS“
.esirnuS ot dellac eh ”,ereh er’eW“
,sdoow eht ni ti tup ot ydob reh koot yddad yM“
.gnimoc saw mrots A
.swobniar gnihsalf dna thgil gninrom eht gnihctac ,welf sporD
.seert fo dnab eht revo dellats yehT
”?ynoloc ruoy morf srovivrus rehto yna ereht ereW“ ,dias eltsihT
.detiaw esirnuS erehw ffilc eht fo pot eht ot esir ot
.doog saw gnihsif ehT
.pu hctac ot srehto eht rof detiaw dna deppots eH
.ylleb s’hsif eht ot detniop redipS
.llug yna sa yltrepxe sa sdniw gnitsug eht gnisu
.deksa nogard egnarts eht ”?ereh efas ti sI“
”?doof yna evah uoy oD“
,snogard gnuoy rehto eht htiw miws ot gninrael—
,mih retfa gnilarips srehtaef
”.neht ,emoh og ll’eW“
.swaperof htob htiw ti no decnuop ehS
.wenk redipS ,ylimaf a deen did ehS
”?stnerap ruoy era erehW“
”?yhW“ ”.meht tfel I .oN“
,redipS denethgirf tI
.won htlaeh fo kaep eht ta saw esirnuS wenk eh ,remmus-dim yB
.dias eltsihT ”,enoyreve toN“
”,snogard rehto yna t’nera ereht tuB“
,derit esirnuS erofeb selim lareves rof tsaoc eht gnola welf yehT
.denekcals niar ehT
,dias eh ”,stnerap yM“
,oot dehsaw redipS
.worromot syawla saw ereht
.gninrom lla aes eht ffo detsug dniw ehT
,ynoloc dlo sih ot reh gnikat deredisnoc eh tnemom a roF
,mih ta dekool dna kcab tas ehS ”?deneppah tahW“
.erofeb thgin eht potffilc eht no tfel dah esirnuS senob hsif eht revo delssut wef a dna
,peelsa llef ehs gnol erofeB
”.su htiw emoC“ .deksa eh
,eman s’esirnuS fo egdelwonk ehT
”.esirnuS dellac m’I“ .deddon ehS
,mih deksa ehs ”?gnivael ew era nehW“
”.emoh a uoy dnif ot evah eW
.sgniw reh no ffulf eht gnicalper erew srehtaef wen gnimaelG
.hsifedalb a fo senips eht ekil
,retaw eht morf hsif gniggans ta tpeda tsomla emaceb esirnuS
”,sgniw ruoy ekahS“
.niht saw ehs rednow oN
peelsa llaf ot dedneterp eH
,deraor aes eht ,delwoh dniw ehT
.gnirps retawhserf eht ot welf yeht sa tnatculer dna yvaeh tlef eH
”.retaw eht fo roloc eht er’uoY .era uoY“
dedaf dah regna dlo eht spahreP
.naeco eht ffo ni devom mrots a sa spordniar gnignits tsrif eht gnignirb
.reh revo gniw sih daerps eh dna gnirevihs reh leef dluoc redipS
,drawrof delggurts ehS
.eugalp eht devivrus ohw snogard eht
,esolc pu nogard dnalni na nees reven d’eH
”.evila llits m’I dna ,eid t’ndid uoY“
,dnuora snogard neeb dah ereht syawlA
,thgin eht otni raf welf yehT
.sgge owt dial syawla snogarD
.delbmuts ehs nehw esirnuS pleh nogard egnarts eht ees ot derussaer saw dna
”?eid stnerap ruoy did oga gnol woH“
noitcifnon eht stsoh osla dna
”?erehwyna retlehs ereht sI“
.emoh reh ekat ot emoc dluow eno oN
senob eht ta dekcip ehS
”.deid retsis ym dnA
,desaercni dna denepeed dniw eht fo dnuos ehT
;redipS rof hguone drah saw tI
.daed lla ylekil tsom erew yawa mih tnes dah ohw snogard eht taht tpecxE
.yab lessum eht ni ylkciuq dehsaw dna
llew ylralucitrap ton
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb uoy rof daer
,sraey ni enoyna ot nekops t’ndah eH
.evila esle enoyna dnif t’ndluoc eW“
.ydob sih revo gnisolc sevaw eht dna
.sserP nosinnaM morf elbaliava
.meht demoorg tsal d’ehs nehw derednow eH
.sffilc eht fo pot eht ta ssarg tew eht no
yab eht otni tuo maws neht
,mih yebo dluow eciov sih erofeb eciwt taorht sih raelc ot dah redipS
.knird dluoc yeht os ,niks a ni
.ti netae dah ehs nehw dias ehs ”,uoy knahT“
.meht nepo dluoc ehs sa tsaf sa slessum gnilbbog saw ehS
.tfola yats ot yllacitnarf gnippalf
.won ekawa ylhguoroht
.hself eht ta teg ot niks hguot sti kcab deppirts neht
.ysaenu redipS edam
,evael t’now uoy fI“
”.em rof ti did syawla amaM
,doof rieht fo emos em evag tnua yM
.hsif rof devid dna
”.neerg ton m’I“
.xaler reh tlef dna sgniw s’esirnuS demoorg eH
.tnemezama ni reh dehctaw redipS
.kcab emac reven eh tub
.ynoloc sih ot reh gnikat
,hguoht ,stnemom wef a ylno retfa niaga retaw eht fo tuo dednuob ehS
”.derdnuh owt tsomla fo tuo devivrus ynoloc ruo fo neves ylnO
,kcab yaw eht lla niar nwolb dah dniw ehT
.flesruoy ot dnik eb dna
”.hsif a uoy gnirb ll’I“
,sraey ni emit tsrif eht rof gnikaw saw eh taht tlef redipS
.tsacdoP slaminA egnartS
,sgniw sih htaeneb deldduh esirnuS
ega reh ta seitivitca sih derebmemer eH
.mih denioj ehs nehw hsaw esirnuS ekam ot edit hgih rof tiaw dluohs eh rehtehw gniredisnoc llits saw eH
.kcisemoh yletuca ,ylneddus saw redipS
.srehtaef-gniw reh fo egnaro-der relap eht ni detcelfer
.yats ot ereh saw ehs dezilaer eh emit tsrif eht roF
ygolohtna eht ni deraeppa yllanigiro
yddad ym rof gnikool tnew I .tfel saw eno on
,rehtorb sih htiw gnihsif
.gnippots tuohtiw nwod gnihsal
,sffilc eht ot mih hsup dniw eht tel dna deppilsedis redipS .gnihsarht sgniw
,reh detius eman ehT
.meht tsniaga deraor dna dehtorf aes ehT
,setarip pihsria ydal fo elpuoc a tuoba seirots trohs fo noitcelloc a si
.srehtaef nwo sih neerp ot detrats dna ,dias eh
.mih ediseb rehtorb sih htiw taeh s’noonretfa eht hguorht peels ot emoh gninruter
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ecargsid sih ta niaga emahs htiw dexim ,thguoht eht ta raef demotsuccanu fo egrus a tlef eH
.nwo reh no eb ot gnuoy oot ylniatrec
.snogard rehto gnoma emoh a reh dnif ot dedeen eh taht yltnatculer dediced eh erofeb keew rehtona saw tI
.nogard dnalni eht was eh nehw gnihsif saw redipS   wahS .C.K yb
.knats regnol on ehs taht
.ylihtaerb derepsihw ehs
.egde ’sffilc eht ot emac yeht retal stnemoM
,aes eht ffo evom ot nageb ezeerb eht dna sffilc eht revo detfil nwad nehw ,gninrom eht ni tuB
nogarD etihW ,nogarD kcalB
.esirnuS ot dias eh ”,kcab oG“
”.emoh mrots eht taeb ot deen eW“
.mih dekcimim esirnuS
,retaw no nus eht ekil enohs ehS
,kcab yrev eht ni tsen gib a eb ot desu erehT .seY“
”.evael ot em dlot sdneirf siH
,spord doolb dima yltnelis gnillaf rehtorb sih neht dnA
,ffilc eht nwod yawflah
,dias dna mih ta pu dekool ehS
”.uoy dnuof I dalg m’I
.sserP ossaciR yb dehsilbup
,lavirra reh retfa keew a naht erom ,thgin enO
,egnaro elap fo hsulb tniaf a yb esolc pu derepmet saw
.peelsa eb ot demees yeht thgil mid eht ni ecnalg tsrif tA
,tsrif kcis tog retsis yM
.did ehs naht ssel eta redipS .sseldne saw
.ylhguoroht dehcterts redipS
,sehcnuah reh no gnittis saw esirnuS
.seye deirrow htiw gnineve eht fo tser eht mih dehctaw ehS
.niaga snogard gnoma ro enola devil eh fi won derac eno oN
”.eromyna snogard gnoma evil t’nac I
”.ecitcarp dna tuo sgniw ruoy dloH
”.neerg s’ohw nogard a nees reven ev’I“
”.esirnuS si siht ;redipS m’I .seY“
.dnim sih fo kcab eht ni evael ot noisiced sih tup dna dexaler redipS
.daed er’yehT“ .deksa eh
.esirnuS dnuora sgniw sih tup eH .enola erew yehT
*** .sffilc eht tsniaga gnikaerb aes eht ot dna niar eht ot gninetsil
.sevaw eht otni dekcud dna
,noonretfa eno htuom evac eht ni gniyl erew yehT .esword dna nus eht ni eil ylpmis ro
.sreh dehsinif ydaerla dah esirnuS
.kcab eht ni tsen a ekam ot sessarg yrd fo sdaolmra ni thguorb dah dna
”.ot tnaw t’nod I“ ”.meht dnif ll’eW
”.gnibburcs trats uoy ecno pu mraw ll’uoY“
.wap ydnas a htiw tuons reh debbur ehS
,seert eht hguorht detrats yehT
.elbatirri dednuos eltsihT
,knurd dah yeht ecnO
.dias esirnuS ”,em rof tpecxE“
.derepsihw ehs ”?ereh sevil ohW“
.ylfeirb dnuora deffins eH
ylitliug llehs eht deppord esirnuS
,ecnartne evac eht drawot dekool eH
..flesruoy ot dnik eb dna
riapsed oga-gnol sih derebmemer redipS
.sgniw sih fo eno rednu delgguns dna
”?ereh pu worg uoy diD“
koob doog a htiw pu lruc ot uoy gnidnimer
.edis s’redipS tsniaga peelsa llef esirnuS
.eciov s’eltsihT gninword
.ksat eht rof edam demees swalc tnulb reh tub
,ffilc eht ffo detsaoc redipS ”.em wolloF“
.ega nwo ruoy sdneirf deen uoY“
.eno txen eht morf rorret-kcom ni delf dna
”.emoh og ot tnaw I“
.niar ot nageb ti sa tsuj
”.deid snogard eht llA .deid lla yehT
.detsuahxe htob erew yeht retfa gnol
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.yawyna sseug dluow nogard eht diarfa-flah dna elixe sih tuoba eltsihT llet ot demahsa oot ,detatiseh eH
.dnalni denrut yeht
,ecnartne evac eht tuo derats eH
,gniroloc der reH
.tsol dah ehs htgnerts dna thgiew eht deniager esirnuS litnu ton—
.reh dnuora sgniw sih depparw redipS
.kaeps dluoc eh erus t’nsaw llits eH
.sih neht dna srehtaef reh gnineerp lausu naht emit erom tneps dna ,dias eh ”,nooS“
.kcis tog enoyrevE“
.wonk uoy ,ereht nogard aes ylno eht eb t’ndluow uoY
,dnalni gnivil dna reverof aes eht gnivael fo thguoht redipS ”.esruoc fo ,htob uoy htiw—
.erif ffo-raf emos morf deirrac rebme na ton dna
.racs eht tuoba nettogrof tsomla dah eH .deksa ehs
,selahw rof kool ot aes ot tuo ylf ro
*** .ylipeels derumrum ehs
.llef yeht erehw seidob evael dluow eugalp yb detatsaved ynoloc a ylno
.erew snolat dekooh s’redipS yaw eht ti rof edam t’nerew swalc reh hguohtla
.ti yrT“ .deddon esirnuS
”.ylimaf a sdeen ehS
”.ecnis reve srovivrus rehto rof gnihcraes neeb ev’I
.dnas fo noom-flah worran a gnisopxe
.hsif evil a dewollaws d’eh hguoht sa tlef hcamots siH
.seye ediw htiw mih ta derats esirnuS
.niar htiw gnimaelg edih reh ,gniggas sgniw reh htiw doots ehS
”?slessum era tahW“
.oot dnal ot moor reh evig ot edisa devom dna evac eht fo pil eht no dednal redipS
.dias nogard egnarts eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.gnihctac rehtob ot hguone gib eno dnif ot elihw a redipS koot tI
,nees ton dah ehs depoh eH
.tuo sgniw reh koohs dna
.sgniw dedlof s’redipS ta debbarg dniw ehT
.msaisuhtne tuohtiw burcs ot nageb dna dnas fo lufwap a pu depoocs esirnuS
.edis sih tsniaga ylthgit esirnuS dleh eH
yad txen eht gninromdim yB
.yas ot tahw wonk t’ndid eh tuB
niaga desirprus saw dna tsen eht otni delttes eH
,ecafrus eht woleb tsuj hsif a fo epahs dewodahs eht was eh nehW
”.esruoc fO .seY“ .deksa ehs
”.rehtie kcis tog reven I dna
.aes eht tsniaga sffilc sti fo elgna eht
.snogard rehto rof gnikool emac I“ ,dias eltsihT
.snolat sih fo eno naht regnol ylecracs llits erew snroh reH
”.srehto xis ro evif tog ev’eW
”.emoh tsomla er’ew kniht I
.ynoga ni hguoht sa dehsarht srehto eht dna nellaf ydaerla dah enO
.snogard rehto dedeen esirnuS hcum woh rebmemer mih edam noitasrevnoc ehT
.emit emos ni dehsaw t’ndah ehs hguoht sa dellems ehs dna
,ekawa deyats redipS tub
,ffilc eht ffo flesmih dehcnual eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,sdniw aes gnitsug eht no dedilg ehs tuB
.erew yeht erehw wenk regnol on eh esuaceb
.yvaeh dna wols erew sevaw ehT .delbuort
.evac eht morf htaed fo llems eht tpews oga gnol dah aes ehT
evac a dnif ot depoh redipS
”,sgniw ruoy moorG“
.ecno thgif a ni saw I“
.nwo sih dnif ot niaga tfel dna
.daed eht dna meht neewteb ecnatsid tup ot regae meht fo htob
.hcaorppa ot emit gnol a nogard der eht koot tI
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,eciwt sgniw sih palf ot dedeen ylno redipS
”,ega ym snogard emos teem ot tnaw did I“
,netfo kcab gnicnalg ,yaw eht del eH
.mih dellik yllatnedicca dna rehtorb ym htiw thguof I“
.dah ehs taht noisserpxe dennuts reh morf wenk tub
.sthgin gnirps yllihc eht no htmraw reh democlew eh dna tsen eht ni mih ot esolc delgguns tpels ehS
”?uoy t’now ,em htiw emoc lliw uoY“
.likasT si eman ym ,ahtalaF“
.pmulp-ybab ylreporp kool ot gnitrats saw ehS
,yks eht koohs rednuht dna
”ykS dna aeS“   :yojne esaelP
,esirnuS brutsid t’ndluow eh os ylluferac pu tog redipS
.srehtaef dlo dna hsurb fo pu edam
.htuom evac a ni dnal ot ezeerb eht nwod dils dna deknab eH
.reh ot txen ni dedaw redipS
,desaelp saw redipS
.thgis ni snogard on erew erehT
.swaperof sih htiw elddim eht dnuora esirnuS gnikool-deifirret a gnipsalc
.sselerutaef dna reehs erew ereh sffilc eht tub—lla ta evac yna—
.sffilc eht fo pot eht ta ssarg eht ni tpels yehT
;eid ot aes ot tuo raf ylf t’ndluow snogard derujni yrev ro kcis yrev ylnO
,em pleh ot enoemos dnif ot tnew I nehw dnA
”.deid dah esle enoyreve thguoht eW
.desae dniw eht fo hctip eht yllaudarG
oga gnol elbbur fo ti deraelc dah redipS
.nogard dehsawnu fo knats evac eht tub
,su nioj ot snogard erom ytrof tuoba dnuof ylno ev’I“
dnas eht ni sevoorg ekam ot ti gnisu
.niaga kcab mih gnivird morf dniw eht peek ot yllacitnarf gnippalf
.ti teg t’nod snogard emoS .eugalp eht s’tI“
.gnirats pots dluow ehs os
”?evil uoy od erehW“
.oot snogard rehto rof gnikool neeb ev’eW“
”,aes eht otni senob eht worhT“ ”.uoy ekil ylf dluoc I hsiw I“
.ecnereffid a gnikam ydaerla erew erac dna doof eht tuB
.evael ot dah I .oN“
.yletaidemmi tsomla aedi eht detcejer tub
.mih tsniaga nael ot dnuora detfihs ehS
.dloc dna smrots morf mih retlehs ot evac efas a
!uoy tem I yad eht seert esoht was I“
.egatnavda reh ot sdniw gniteffub eht esu ot woh wonk ot gnuoy oot ,gnuoy yrev saw ehs :yhw was redipS
,oot dednal nogard der eht retal setunim wef A
.evac eht otni dereep esirnuS
.mih denioj eltsihT
.demraw retaw eht dna dessergorp gnirpS
:meht woleb tsaoc eht ezingocer ot nageb redipS
”,eltsihT“ .drah gnirevihs
.dellac redipS ”,ereh dnaL“
,emas eht did nogard egnarts eht mih dniheB
.reh tuoba od dluohs eh tahw
.retaw eht fo tuo ti deggans dna sgniw sih deppid eh
?mih nettogrof yeht daH .sdneirf sih
.niaga emoclew eb dluow eh dna
.gniwollof saw esirnuS erus ekam ot kcab decnalg neht
evac eht morf flesreh dehcnual ehS
.seert tnebdniw htiw deppot dna sevac htiw dekcop niaga ecno erew sffilc ehT
.pu doots redipS ”.neht toN .oN“
.setib wef tsal eht reh evag eH
.esirnuS sa dehcterw sa dekool eh ,hguoht ,tnemom eht tA
,yawykS ,koob tsetal reH
.sevaw eht evoba wol detsaoc neht
os yab lessum eht ot pirt rehtona dna
”?retsis a ro rehtorb a evah uoy diD“
,laffo eht deplug dna nepo hsif eht tib ehS ”.stug sti etiB“
.rehtaew eht ni gnimoc egnahc a desnes redipS tub
mih ot txen pu delwarc esirnuS nehw
,edit wol litnu ezod dna hsif ,nwad ta
.ecnartne eht ot gnulc nogard fo tnecs oN
thgin eht rof deppots yeht nehW
.mih ta kool ot denrut redipS
sffilc eht tsniaga derumrum frus eht nehw gnineve eno etal ,yllaniF
.reh hctac ot dedeen eh esac ni ylesolc dewollof redipS dna
.esool slessum eht yrp ot woh reh dewohs dna
.denruter reve eh fi mih llik ot desimorp dah ynoloc dlo sih ni snogard ynam ooT
.tnemom a rof thgit reh degguh redipS
”.sgniw ruo moorg dna nus eht ni tis og s’teL“
.esirnuS ekat em tel tsael ta
keew txen eht revO
esirnuS ot ti thguorb eH
.waj sih rednu elzzum reh desserp esirnuS
,mih detatimi ehS
,hguoht ,noisiced sih derebmemer eh emit ot emit morF
.krad dna ediw seye reh
”!uoy htiw ereh yats ot tnaw I“
,egde ffilc eht revo
htiw llits dna toh saw thgin ehT
,dehsif yeht sa derettahc ehS
.hsif ot emit tseb eht t’nsaw edit woL .deksa ehs
.reh dnuora deldduh sgniw reh htiw nwod dehcuorc esirnuS
.dias redipS ”,wonk t’nod I“
,dias dna swaj reh dekcil ehS
.gelerof sih dniheb wolloh eht otni tuons reh desserp ehS
,mih ot txen pu delruc llits esirnuS dnif ot ekow redipS
,detuohs esirnuS tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.dniw eht otni yltcerid ylf ot denrut yehT
noitcif yrruf dna ysatnaf setirw ohw
.slessum tae dna dnas eht ni yalp dluoc esirnuS
.niaga gniw sih rednu delgguns dna
,llef niar yvaeh ,drah a noon dnuorA
”.mih no seilf erew erehT .daed saw eh tub
,aes eht dna yks eht ni derettilg srats dna
.flesmih neve ton
.edisni deirrucs dna htuom evac eht ni dednal yehT
.meht revo hctaw ot seno dlo dna htiw yalp ot seno gnuoy
.ynoloc a ni gnoleb t’ndid redipS
.sffilc eht tsniaga aes eht fo raor eht draeh redipS tsal tA
.woh detartsnomed dna ,dias redipS
.eman terces s’nogard a htiw detsurt saw redipS ecnis
.ti tegrof t’ndluow ehs os
,peelsa llef ehs litnu flesreh ot eman sih gnirettum reh draeh eH
.dniw eht ni syawedis dehsals niar erehw
.deid amam ym neht dnA
,yltneuqerf derednow eH
,sevaw debbew-maof no demaelg nuS .dedne niar ehT
,selcnu dna stnua dna snisuoc sih ,stnerap sih fo thguoht eH
daeh sih morf kcab devruc snroh deroloc-enob sih dna elam saw eH
,hguone esolc saw ehs ecnO
ffo ti gnittup erom on saw erehT
,redrah detsug dniw ehT
.esirnuS fo tnorf ni gniw a gnulf eH
”?kcen ruoy no racs taht teg uoy d’woH“
yawyna ,tey tsuj evael ot esiw eb t’ndluow tI
”,ahtalaF s’eman yM“
.naeco eht ta wap a devaw esirnuS
?mih ees ot dalg eb yeht dluoW
aes eht otni evaw gnitaerter a desahc esirnuS sa dehctaw eH
.og ll’ew spots niar eht ecnO .neht ,thgir llA“
,niaga htuom s’evac eht ni erew yeht nehW
.sgel reh dnuora dehtorf evaw a sa laeuqs a htiw kcab gnarps neht
.yks dehsaw-niar a ni gnisir saw nus ehT
.aes eht evoba thgif gnihsals ,suoiciv a yb dewollof sdrow—kcab nekat eb t’ndluoc taht sdrow
.sgniw ym moorg ot woh wonk t’nod I“
shtab :mhtyhr a otni llef syad rieht
,llehs a htiw gniyalp saw esirnuS
.os yas t’ndid dna gnikaeps fo tibah eht fo tuo saw redipS tub
.kaeps ot ssenwen fo lluf oot saw eH
,dias dna waj s’esirnuS delzzun eH
,stelni dna syab sti
.mih rof tfel eltsihT ecnelis gninetsil eht llif dluohs eh wenk redipS
.yalp ot woh nettogrof oga gnol dah eh dna
,retaw htiw mih gniyarps
.yliad devorpmi slliks gniylf reH
”.ecin ton s’tI“
.mih ot txen delttes dna
,tsaoc eht gnola welf snogard owt ehT
.erofeb thgin eht nwolf dah ehs naht retteb ylniatrec tub
.gge eht fo tuo htaerb tsrif sih ekil dniw yniar dloc eht ni gnihtaerb
reh dnuora derettacs sllehs lessum ytpme eht ta dekop esirnuS
.redipS ta flesreh gnulf ehs retal tnemom A
,oot ,detcepxe redipS naht reivaeh dna reggib hcum saw eH
tub…og ot emit saw tI
.dias ehs ”,ecin er’uoY“
.redipS ta dekool dna revo dellor esirnuS nehw
nossel emas eht mih gnivig rehtom sih gnirebmemer ,detiaw eH
.moorg ot mih rof tuo sgniw pmad reh gnidaerps
.dekrej dna dekcub ti sa noitanretsnoc ni gnirats ,dias ehs
.krahs llub a ekil tliub
”,nur ot evah ll’eW“
regnol elihw elttil a retfA
,dias esirnuS nehT .oga gnol
,mih ylno dah esirnuS
”.uoy htiw emoc ll’I“ ”?ni og I yaM“ ”.stnerap rieht dna stnerap rieht dna stnerap ym morf ,srehtaef fo sdnasuohT
,revir eht morf retaw thguorb I—
”.gnihcraes fo shtnom fo tuo
*** ”.gniog htob er’eW .oot gniog m’I“
.dnalni raf erew yeht gnol erofeB
.aes yarg a otni llef niar yarg erehw
.kcis tog reven I tuB
,mih no ecnedneped reh dna