”.ereh krow I regnol eht erom ynam ees lliw I taht kniht I“ .deddon deraY
lliw–“ tsrif eht ta neht dna ”–uoy neht–“
”.edom derreferp ym ton si taht tub
”.metsyS eht ot gnidaeh seno eht fo tsrif ehT“ ”?hO“
”?emaN eurT uoy era…taht sI“
,colB naissuR-oniS eht otni gniylf saw eh
,erehwon dna erehwyreve morf emoc ot demees taht sthgil yb til saw tI
.dehcuorc dna pets a yawa dekcab ohw
.tropria eht ot ti edam dah eh litnu ,dezilaer eh ,tsael tA
.pu denethgiarts deraY
.hgih no doots nus ehT
”.no gnivil ydaerla era uoY
.gniyd ekil ton s’ti esimorp uoy fI“
.srebmun eht gnituohS
”?sruoh thgie-ytroF“
,egaggul ylno sih saw taht gab citsalp llams eht otni ti kcap ot tuoba saw eh sa ,dna
,thgil tsuj fo thgis gniniamer tsal ehT
.pey ,su si tahT“ .deddon emaN eurT
.gnippalc dna gnihgual dna gninnirG
”?elimS“ ”.elims neht dna
.llew sa uoy teem ot eciN ?yllaeR ?sanoJ“
.yaw eht yb ,errabeD“
”?ereh eid lliw I tuB“
.meh eht ot sredluohs eht morf nwod gnidaeh sepirts edacorb dlog owt dah cirbaf eht neht dna
.strap niatrec rebmemer ylno dna
.sgar fo elip eht depsar
.noisserpxe deye-ediw rehtona htiw tem saw smotsuc hguorht pots ehT
.did eh oS .ti rebmemer
.erom ecno swap reh deppalc neht ,deltrats dekool emaN eurT
”.’tiuq ot ydaer ma I
.delims neht ,daeh reh detlit nemow desserd-llew eht fo enO .deksa emaN eurT
,a899a323#ihgzereZ deraY sa ti wenk eh dezilaer eh —
,ecno nees dah eh terref a fo deraY dednimer taht tros emos fo lamina rehtona
— hcihw rettam t’nseod ti os ,rehto hcae morf tnereffid si taht hcum oot decneirepxe ton evah uoy — uoy fo eno ,woN
.uoy derutcip I woh yltcaxe ton era uoY“ ,dias eh ,yllaniF
ton…lliw I“ .denworf deraY
,esimorp tonnac I os ,deid reven evah I“
.dias eno depahs-terref eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tcnitsni no ti koohs deraY dna dnah sih tuo dehcaer nam delsuot ehT ”!erusaelp a ,ihgzereZ .rM“ ”.ih ,hU“
,yldednimtnesba deddon eH
,epacsdnal a ciasorp os ot snoitasnes tnasaelpnu
?gnihtyna leef I lliW“
,won yteixna ruoy rof noitacidem ekil dluow uoy fI“
.deggurhs nosrep tpircsednon ehT
.tsael ta ,edistuo eht morf gnimussanU
.enil eht hguorht no evom dna kcab elims ylno dluoc deraY
.deraeppasid nehT
”.setunim evif naht regnol stsal krof eht fi noitatuper emos tsoc seod ti hguoht ,nac I“
”.eid ot tsuj raf siht nettog evah t’nac I…t’nac I
.elddirg a morf draeh eb dluoc sgge fo elzzis eht dna rab a denil sloots der dna revlis erehw ,edisni mraw yllufthgiled tub ,edistuo yllihc saw tI
”.sey ,detlah eb ro tiuq rehtie lliw uoy ,yllautneve os
,no sucof ot mees t’ndluoc eh taht ecaf tpircsednon a
”.tey metsyS eht ni ton ,oS“
.revoc eht ees dluoc ehs taht os ti denrut eH
.tsael ta ,em fo noitrop a rO .em si ti ,seY“
.saw eh neht dnA .elimS
.yticitnehtua fo reyal a dedda hcihw kni eht ot raems a gnidda
.gnihcterts a neht dnA .thgil tsuj
.ecno ta sneppah lla ti erofeb setunim ereh teg I dna ,gnol os rof demaerd I ”!owT“
,llat pu dehcterts eH
tsuj eh ,noitisnart eht leef ton did eh
”.dehtolc eb ot tnaW .ti tnaw
.syad eerht ni emit tsrif eht rof llits yltcefrep erew yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”…emiT ylnO ehT…ylnO ehT
”?seY“ ”?detsaf evah uoY“
,dleif ssarg a ni llih llams a pota tas eH
.oga gnol os morf
?emaN…eurT“ .seye yldneirF
,esuap a saw erehT
.eb ot desaec ihgzereZ deraY ,taht htiw dnA
.sraey thgil ,pu sretemolik
.noitanimreted eht ,raef eht
”.gniht ’knuks‘ elohw eht dezilanretni yllaer reven I sseug I“
dna cinilc dloc morf egnahc neddus eht ta gnilevram ,daeh sih koohs eH
neht dna ,taht erutciP
”.haey ,ma I sseug I“
.nwodtnuoc a nageb elbat eht sa ylkciuq nwod eeffoc sih tes deraY ”.sdnoces neT“
”?kaeps uoy naC .deraY“
.won gnidnats saw eh erehw htiw suourgnocni os
,uoy dewohs I tahw yllacisab meht wohs dna evirra lliw ediug a neht dna
saw tnatropmi gnihtemos fo yromem a hguoht sa
.ruf kcalb depirts-etihw dna tuons gnirepat a
.sknaht fo erutseg a evag dna deddon deraY
.dias tnega eht
.htob nialliv dna oreh deredisnoc eb thgim ohw enoyna ot eud seye yraw eht htiw dedrager osla saw eh
.sdnah sih ta nwod dekool eH ”.wonk t’nod…I“
”.pu uoy teg su tel ,no emoC“
”.sey ,maerD I nehW sI emaN eurT yM wonK I emiT ylnO ehT“
,gnihtyna naem ton thgim taht elihw dna ,etihw yrev saw ehS
.detuohs eh ”!eerhT“
dna eliforp eht fo epahs eht ni ereht ylraelc saw ecnalbmeser ehT
.ereht eb ot detnaw eno oN
,eb ot ti detcepxe eh sa etor dna llud sa saw
.gnilims saw ti hguoht sa dednuos eciov ehT
.dekrof I“ ”?taht saw tahW“
”.edis-sys eurt eb lliw emas eht taht snaem ti sa
.ti ot enil a deppilc esrun eht litnu dnah sih fo kcab eht ni eldeen eht eciton t’ndid eh sa
.gnorw og lliw gnihtoN“
,neeb ecno dah yeht erehw stops eht revo bmuht sih debbur eH
.tuo dehtaerb dna ,seye sih desolc
?sey ,dnatsrednu uoY
.rekaeps evitan a neeb evah ton llew sa tsuj dluoc ehs dna
”,citsatnaF“ ”.os kniht I ,seY“
.ereht…ylpmis saw eH
”?thgir ,laed gib ruoy s’tI
.sredluohs sih morf ylbatrofmoc gnignah cirbaf eht tlef eH
,wols ro neddus ton saw tI
”.hcnual eht htiw gnorw seog gnihtemos esac ni tsuj esoppus I
.deb taht no ereht ,derohcna deniamer teef sih elihw smra sih fo pu gnihcterts A
,etelpmoc sah daolpu ehT
”,eno tsal eht er’uoY“
,haaa gnol a ni tuo ti tel dna ,htaerb rehtona koot eH
dekool taht nemow dna sknuks rehto fo elggag a gnidulcni ,edisni elpoep nezod wef a erew erehT
”noisseceS“ saw sihT
’.9bb9acaa#s’enihpesoJ ta eb ot tnaw
”?em rebmemer uoy oD
”.gnirob tsom s’reverehW“
.psarg ot esle gnihton saw ereht tub
.seno wen ynam yrev oS“
saw od ot dedeen eh lla dna ,ereht thgir
.ecalp ton dluoc eh taht ssenruos detalp-lekcin emos fo htob ,etsat gniniamer tsal eht
”.taht rof ydaer m’I fi wonk t’nod I“ .ecnarussaer fo
.hguone laer tlef tI
”.gnol os retfa renrael tsaf a eb dluow uoy derugif I“
.psag a ni delahxe dna htuom sih denepo eH
,secnetnes dna sdrow otni pu enil ot segap eht no slobmys eht teg ton dluoc eH
.emaN eurT morf hgual a draeh eH
”.won ma I tahw wonk t’nod I .saw I“
”.edis rehto eht no ydaerla era uoY
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,tiuq dluohs eh taht demrofni gnieb fo kcohs eht ,noitasrevnoc ehT
.flesmih fo thgis eht derebmemer eH
.slianregnif demmirt-llew emas eht
.tiuq lliw uoY .on ,eid toN“
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”noisseceS“
.siht ekil kool I“
,tnecca colB R-S emos saw ti fi ylfeirb derednow eH
”.ereht teem dna secalp gnitseretni dnif tsuj eW .es rep ,sretrauqdaeh on si erehT“ .dias sanoJ
.stnega thgilf eht fo lla fo
.mih evoba eulb dna sselduolc saw yks ehT
.dedne tsuj seiromem eht neht dnA
,tniop taht tsap gnihtyna rebmemer ot gniyrt ,daeh sih detlit eH
”?kaeps uoy naC .deraY“
.roolf yerg ,gniliec yerg ,sllaw yerg fo ebuc a ni gnidnats ylpmiS
.gniraeh naht ssel dna erom gnihtemos hguorht
”.uoy teem ot eciN
”.mU“ ”?leef uoy od woH“
.emaN eurT ma I .sey a sa taht ekat lliw I“
.tnereffid oS
.ot tnaw ton od uoy fi krof ot deen ton od uoY“
.pis a rof yllacitamotua ti detfil deraY dna mih erofeb decalp saw eeffoc fo gum A
”.daets reh ni ereh ma I os ,thginot ereh eb ton dluoc ellehciM
”,yawyna ,ytilicaf pukcab a si erehT
,elpmet reh ot pat a dna elims yls a htiw kcab tropssap sih dednah ehS
.skeehc sih ni ssentoh a tlef eh taht revo saw noitasrevnoc eht retfa ylno saw tI
.thguoht eh ,rof lla saw ti tahw si sihT
.sdrawkcab llef dna detuohs neht ,etihw dna kcalb
”?oot ,siht od nac I dnA“ ”.sey ,tiuq ehS“
”.ti gnidaer pu dniw t’nod I fi yrarbil eht ot ti evig ll’I .uoy knaht ,lleW
”?gnirutcip uoy erew tahW“
.koob sih fo segap eht ta daetsni erats dluow eh
.mih ot txen regnessap eht ot ti gnidnah ,deggurhs dna
.knuks eht ediseb gnidnats namow trohs a ylneddus saw erehT ”–kool nac I
.dias emaN eurT ”,og uoy erehT“
.dehgual ehS ”?taht od nac uoY“
sderaY owt eht fo rewen eht ta detniop ehs ”–tiuq uoy fI
”.ni kcab seiromem s’krof eht gnigrem fo noitpo eht evah
.og lliw I kniht ton od I“
”.ytrap eht nioj ot eno tsal eht eb ot detnaw tsuj uoY .hctib a fo nos ydeerg uoY“
”.thgiE fo licnuoC eht htiw sgnirts emos dellup I os dna
,noonretfa siht morf derebmemer eh sehsimelb dna riah tahw ylno htiw
.deggurhs dna delims emaN eurT
.gnihgual ,mih ediseb deraeppa emaN eurT
.wonk ton did eh ,ton ro ytiunitnocsid yna saw ereht rehtehW
.ssecorp lanimil taht hguorht tis ot detnaw eno oN
”.ellehciM fo serutcip nees ev’I
,skoobe dna skcabrepap sa meht esahcrup nac uoy erehw kni.fles-
,wonk uoY“ .dehgual eH
.tnorf reh ssorca depparts seidoog lacidem suoirav fo reelodnab a ot ti gnippilc erofeb telbat eht no gnihtemos depiws dna deddon ehS
,lamina flah dna namuh flah gnihtemos
.scitilop no gnihtemos saw tI
.tuo dehtaerb mih fo owt neht dna ,ni dehtaerb deraY ,dnopser dluoc ehs erofeB
.swap reh deppalc — eb ot reh derebmemer won eh sa — knuks ehT ”!tnellecxE“
,efilretfa na fo noitseuq eht derewsna ton evah llits eW“
.gnieb otni sehtolc sih kniht ot tseb sih did deraY
.mih ot emoc ton did rO
”.retfa gnihton si erehT ?eeS“
,tuo ehtaerb uoy nehw neht dna ,ni ehtaerB .xaleR“
.t’now uoy esoppus I ,oN“
.reh fo tseb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
.erutseg eht denruter eh ,noitatiseh s’tnemom a retfa dna
,retnec lacidem eht ot mih nevird dah ohw nam eht fo tnecca detlits ,deppilc emas eht dah hsilgnE reH
.elims suoituac a ot noisufnoc morf detfihs noisserpxe reh dna ecaf reh no demoolb gnidnatsrednu fo kool A
.tnemom taht morf flesym fo ecnatsni wen a detaerc I
.spahrep ,tiftuo etirovaf ruoY
.nwog repap a fo seveels eht hguorht smra sih hsup dna eborsid ot detcurtsni saw eh erehw moor gnitiaw a ot detcerid saw eH
,todeloT ,koob reh morf retpahc a si yrots s’yadoT
,dah eh sa staef hcus deniatta dah ohw esoht ot dedroffa saw taht ecnerefed eht htiw detaert saw ihgzereZ deraY hguohtlA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.etelpmoc ylraen si refsnart eht tub ,oN“
.raems taht cimim ot elbissopmi tub lla eb dluow tI
.mis etavirp a ni era eW“ ”?ew era erehW“
.meht htiw gnola gnitnuoc saw deraY ,ruof tih yeht emit eht yB
.erom ecno eciov eht emac
,llew sa lacisyhp eht ot dednetxe dah ,dezilaer eh ,ssenbmun ehT
.nees dah deraY sotohp eht ekil dekool ehs taht tcaf eht rof tub ,devom ehs yaw eht
,reffo eht tpecca ton did llits deraY
”.uoy htiw gnikaeps ma — emaN eurT laer eht — I dna
.ellehciM dna emaN eurT ekil yliree
.liat tfoS .mrof eninimeF
,sselehtenon ,ereht saw ti tub ,srae sih hguorht ti raeh ton did eH
”.duol tuo kaeps ro elims ot deen ton lliw uoy dna ,erutan dnoces emoceb lliw tI ?ees ,erehT“
.gnilims saw ti ekil dednuos llits eciov ehT
.gnivael saw eh dlrow eht ta tuo gnikool naht retteb saw ti tub
”?rebmemer
.nwod gnitnuoc saw enoyreve dezilaer neht dna dnuora dekool eH
.seitoob nwo sih htiw dedivorp neve saw eH
, yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.lamina eht morf kcab detrats dna flesmih ta nwod dekool eH ”?spahrep ,dekaN“
.sregnif sih no sdap yrevlis esoht fo enoN .stcatnoc on tuB
”.gniht a leef ton yltrohs lliw uoy ,gnol taht tiaw nac uoy fi os — hsur eht dnatsrednu uoy
”?metsyS eht ni eb ll’I neht tuB“
,yako‘ ,kniht uoy fo eno
.pots lliw ecnatsni tahT .gnihtoN ?nehT“
.snoilednad htiw yllarebil dettod
dna fles-tsop/mf.rohcna ta
.elims dnik a mih evag dna telbat reh morf pu dekool esrun ehT
.dnah a reffo ot nwod denael dna dehgual ,mih erofeb doots taht epahs ehT
,niks krad emas eht gniees ,meht ta kool ot sdnah sih detfil eH
”?gniyd ekil ti sI
.denworf eH ”.wonk t’nod I“
,tuo niht ot nageb eh taht llat oS
,ni nur I taht selcric eht gnoma tsael ta
,tsrif ta swodniw eht tuo derats eH .worg dna
.tniop taht ot teg ot syad wef a slavirra wen sekat ti yllausU !enod lleW“
.snoitome dna sgnileef sih fo lla ssapmocne ot daerps noos dah hcihw
.riah delsuot ylluftra htiw nam gnilims yllauteprep a dna
,tnecs gniniamer tsal eht
.seires fleS-tsoP eht ni dnoces eht
”?neht neppah lliw tahw dnA“
,trofmoc fo enot a tsniaga derraj hcihw ,lanif os erew yehT
,kaeps uoy raeh dna evom uoy ees ot yppah tsuj ma I
.tnasaelpnu syaw lla ni saw ti taht saw rebmemer did eh tahw tub
,gnidda ,ylyrw delims ehS
.tnaruatser a fo thgil ymaets ,mid eht ot tsujda ot tnemom a koot seye s’deraY
,ssenbmun fo teknalb a rednu yteixna gnimlehwrevo taht deirub dah dnim sih fo noitca evitcetorp emos tey dna
kstukaY ni dednal yllanif eh nehw daernu deniamer koob ehT
.raelc dna prahs tub ,dekaN
,niks tfos ,htoomS
”?yawa tnew…tsuj ti neht dnA“
…pans dluow eh taht thguoht eh litnu elddim eht ni gnirepat
.ecnetsixe fo gninnigeb eht fo ssenneddus eht derebmemer eH
.nrael ot tol a dah eh derugif eh tub ,mih desirprus siht yhw erus t’nsaw eH
,xob yarg deddirg a ni pu wohs slavirra wen ,yllausU
,ytirbelec a fo gnihtemos era uoy tub
”.daeh nwo ym fo hguone deifirret ma I
,neht dna ,sbuh tisnart eht dnuora pu tliub taht snwot dna seitic eht gnihctaw
,morf emaN eurT nees dah eh taht elgna tnereffid eht derebmemer eH
.modeerf latot dna etelpmoc dna secaf gnilims eseht rof lla saw tI ”!enO“
,sredluohs eht dnuora mih guh ot redro ni gnippalc deppots emaN eurT
.draeh eh lla detrotsid dah ssenbmun gnimlehwrevo eht fi ro
”.ecaps pu seerf ecnatsni na nehw sesaercni yticapac metsyS taht edistuo morf dlot era ew tub
.yhw wonk t’nod I .oN“
I‘ ,flesruoy ot knihT
.dlot saw eh sa did dna deddon eH
,tuo dehtaerb ,ni dehtaerB .deddon deraY
.ecalp ton dluoc eh taht yaw a ni gnibrutsid saw wodahs a fo kcal eht dna
.yalpsid skrowerif a htiw pu til swodniw ehT
.ten‘ eht ni kcab va ym ekil rehtaR
.htaed ekil tlef taht gnihtyna edulcni ton did deviecer I taht seiromem eht
,hsog‘ ,flesruoy ot yas dna tiftuo taht fo kniht
,ssenerawa sih fo tuo dna ni detfird taht sesion ehT
”.ti deen t’now I“ ”?yhW“
.ihgzereZ .rM ,esaelP“
”noisseceS“   yojne esaelP
”.rebmemer I mrof rehto taht otni kcab pils ti tel tsuj I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.yawa setunim wef a ylno era hcnual dna noisseces ,emoc tuB
.era ydaerla uoY“ .hgual a neht dna
”.pots ylpmis secneirepxe ehT
tsacdop a sa yllaires desaeler gnieb si fleS-tsoP
— revewoh ,setunim net ni si erudecorp ruoY .edivorp nac I
,neht dna ,elkcuhc tfos A
krof s’deraY ”.pots tsuj yehT
,VI na ecalp lliw I .ereh nwod yal dluow uoy fI
”.ti ot desu teg ll’I esoppus I tub ,yllaer toN“
.xelpmoc eciffo gnimussanu na ot mih koot hcihw — ssenbmun fo teknalb taht htaeneb
,emit revo regrem eht lortnoc ot woh nrael lliw uoy dnA
”?tceffe sekat noisseces litnu gnol woh ,oS“
ti fo retteb thguoht eh
,dias dna rehtona neht
.teef sih ot depleh eb flesmih gnittel ,tsal ta wap eht koot neht
”?thgie fo licnuoC eht uoy era…siht sI
,os did yeht sa dna ,htoob eht otni dils meht fo htoB
.ecno ta gnireehc nageb enoyrevE
dliub ot yteixna swolla taht ssenllud fo epyt ralugnis taht saw ti tub ,llud saw kstukaY ot thgilf tsal ehT
”?sey ,eludehcs a no era eW
,llew…saw yregrus ehT
— rac kcalb a fo kcab denoitidnoc-ria eht otni detnuhs saw eH
.enilno eerf rof daer ro
,deraY no erusserp gnidnamed ,neddus a saw erehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.devirra ylwen eht htiw spleh ti taht dnif I tub ,yrassecen ton si trap tahT“
.llew os hsilgnE ekops namow eht taht ykcul neeb dah eH
.noonretfa eht fo taeh eht otni tuo mih del dna dnah eht yb mih koot ohw nam thgils a yb mialc egaggab ta tem saw eH
,namuh a deniatnoc evah yam taht sgar fo elip ytrid a ,slaudividni desserd-llew eerhT
,tnega smotsuc eht fo
.seitoob repap ,etihw htiw roolf eht no dehsiws ohw ffats tneiciffe ,mlac dna elit etihw htiw tem saw eh ,edisnI
”.owt-ytneves ekil eroM“
oga shtnom dna skeew fo seiromem ynam os
”.seno wen evah lliw uoy tub ,diarfa ma I ,retnuocne siht rebmemer ton lliw uoY
.flesmih ta nwod kool ot drawrof daeh sih detlit eh ,evom ot woh — wohemos — gnirebmemeR
.taht wenk eh woh erus ton saw deraY hguoht ,gnilims saw ehs –tI
”.ma I tub ,pu siht gnikcip era uoy hcihw htiw ssenkciuq eht ta desirprus eb ton dluohs I taht wonk I .tsaf saw tahT“
.sdneirf gniteem dna ,eeffoc elbirret gniknird ,renid a ni gnittiS
.erongi ot gniyrt ylsuoiduts erew yeht elpoep yb dednuorrus sriahc elbatrofmocnu ni gnittis ton
,degrem neht dna dekrof tsuj I nehw tub
,stserof fo sksuh tnrub ro sniatnuom erab ro ssarg tpewsdniw ro tresed htiw decalper saw lla nehw
.tuo ehtaerB .ni ehtaerB
.detiaw srehto neves erehw htoob renroc a ot revo deddap knuks ehT
— dnah dereffo reh fo sregnif eht delggiw ehS
,dias dna — waP ?wap
.gnissim saw tnalpmi xetrocoxe railimaf-gnol eht erehw kcen sih fo kcab eht ta hcuot ot pu dnah rehto sih dehcaer neht
.hsiw uoy woh dehtolc flesruoy erutciP“ ”…I od woH .sey…hU“
”?renid a ta teem uoY“
,’!won thgir taht gniraew saw I taht hsiw I
”?suovren uoy erA“
,ti fo tsom rof peelsa etiuq ton ,ekawa etiuq ton gnihtemos saw deraY
.rethgual fo tuohs a tuo tel eH
.fles-tsop ta skoob eht dnif nac uoy
,krof rewen eht ot derutseg tub ,denworf eH
.yletaidemmi yregrus eht ot uoy teg lliw ew dna
.enif si tI .deraY ,oN“
.daetsni flesmih dnuora gnikool
”.owt tif ylisae tonnac hcihw ,metsys s’cinilc daolpu eht ni llits era uoY
,siht ekil–“ .ekops namuh ehT
,gnitset fo esoprup eht rof noitacol yraropmet a ni si ecnatsni sihT“
”.tsal ta ecaf ot ecaf teem ot yppaH .sanoJ“
.elbmert mih edam sdrow ehT
”–mun dna srettel esoht gnirebmemer ot desu teg osla lliw uoY
.sevlesmeht decudortni licnuoc eht fo tser ehT
?retfa eno tsrif eht eb ot tnaw t’ndid uoY
.denworf ehS ”?koob a tnaW“
fo epahs a htiw detnorfnoc ,seye sih nepo deknilb eH
,smotsuc dna gninalped fo ,gnidnal fo tca ehT
.nrael lliw uoY
,tsirw eht fo tsiwt trepxe na htiw tropssap sih depmats tnega ehT
”.no yrt ot tog I bwaht ecin taht gniraew eb ot ekil dluow I“
.mih erofeb gnidnats knuks eht tsuj htiw ,enog saw ehs neht dnA
.noisseces erofeb lavirra tsal ehT“
.raeh ot mih rof hguone duol tsuj rae sih ni derumrum ehs
.noilednad a ta dekculp dna ,nwod dehcaer
,gniog erew yeht erehw eb ot detnaw enoyrevE
.rof saw ti tahw si sihT
.tnereffid…saw gnihtyreve hguoht ,tsael ta dekrow taorht siH
.yltsom ,levird poP
,pu denethgiarts ylwols — woh ton hguoht
”?koob ruoy em gnivig tsuj…uoy erA“
,tuhs seye sih gnitniuqS
.neeb dah syawla eh fi sa tnemrag eht gniraew ylpmis saw
”?ton ti si ,eno tsal eht eb ot detnaw uoy yhw si sihT“
”,revo lla teem eW“
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.ytilibiduani ot tsomla demmid tnaruatser eht fo esion eht
”,tem evah I taht tsrif eht era uoY“
,epahs eht ta pu derats eH
.tihs hguot ,os ,uoy erussaer ot od nac I elttil si erehT“
.neht ,mih ot ekops eciov railimaf ,tfos A
”.thgir eb yam uoy kniht I