.tfard pmub dnoces tsal a morf tixe no tib a delggiw rac eht dna
,srotcod eht htiw laed ot dah I nehw toN
.semag oediv no yenom dna emit hcum oot yaw gnidneps elihw
detnaw I gniht ylno eht dna rae ym ni gnignir tnatsnoc eht dna stnioj gnihca eht dda uoy nehT
hcterts tnorf eht nwod demaercs ew sa yerp fo tiusrup ni sevlow yrgnuh fo kcap gnilwoh
,avliS coruD naeS yb
.esuap a saw erehT
.etar siht ta dik eht hctac ot elba eb reven d’yeht
stniartser eht htiw nevE
,eerf teg ot gniwalc meht leef dluoc I hguoht neve
,ylikcul dna ,hsup sih htiw drawrof dehcrul rac ehT
.enil ni srac erom dedeen ew ,llitS
.egac sti morf dehsaelnu neeb ylneddus dah hcihw lamina dliw a ekil
.trops ruo ni ecar tseggib eht niw dna
dnatsdnarg niam eht ni dworc eht fo raor eht gniraeh ,flesym ot desruc I
,ecar dluoc I os tsuj
.rac enin-ytnewt eht morf evohs rehtona tlef I nehw s’tahT
,kcab gnidloh neeb d’I
”.nwod sdniw gniht siht sa ylerriuqs teg annog s’tI .ereht ni gnaH
.elzzum ym ot elims a gnirb ot hguone saw galf derekcehc eht ekat dik taht gniees
.su dniheb selcihev fo niart eht morf gnimoc gnihsup eht lla htiw neve evoorg wol eht otni gud dna gnorts dleh srac ruO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,llaw eht drawot pu toohs dna
.saw reve I ekil toN
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.emit thgir eht tsuj ta dnuora emoc ot gninnigeb saw rac nmad siht ekil tlef tI .yllaniF
.sleeh ruoy ta ’nitib si enin-ytnewt ehT“
etepmoc dluoc I os tsuj
.dik eht kcerw ot ton dah I noitartnecnoc fo ecnuo yreve koot tI
.ti deppac I tub ,htaerb ym rednu rettum ot detrats I ”—siht rof dlo oot gnitteg m’I“
,deeps erom tnaem ecnatsiser dniw sseL
.dias notfarC ”,dedeen ew tahw tog ew ,yakO“
.otni depparts saw I niffoc latem ,egral eht tcerroc revo ot ton gniyrt
.rac eht edisni gnineppah saw tahw tuoba evian yletelpmoc saw eH  ?feihc werc wollac a hcus em evig ot evah yeht did yhw ,tsirhC       ”.seod syawla tI“
.dnoces a rof neve
tellub gnimaercs eno otni su gninrut
,niaga kcab ti denrut I sa elttorht eht gnirehtaef dna noitcerid etisoppo eht ni leehw gnireets eht gniknarc
”.elbaliava eno ylno eht eb ot deneppah tsuj uoY .tsaf eb ot desoppus era shateehc esuac kcab uoy thguorb kciR ,oN“       .ruoh rep selim derdnuh owt revo gnivird
margeleT dna rettiwT no yggodikahK@ m’I
.elbatrofmoc saw I erehw ,skcart trid eht ta
stip eht ni stops eerht gnisol pu dedne I
hcnurc egac latem ym draeh I
.og ot erehwon htiw dna
,enal elddim eht ni elttes ot decrof saw I
”!stops yna ’nissim uoy ,yeH !oohW“
,etunim a ni ereh evila netae teg annog erew eW .timmaD
.trapa ti pir ot gnitpmetta erew rac eht tsniaga gnihsup erew taht secrof eht fi sa demees tI
kcart suomrone siht ta spal ffo kcit dluoc uoy ylkciuq woh em dezama llits ti ,emit siht lla retfA
.enil hsinif/trats eht ot kcab dedaeh ew sa stops erom owt ffo kcip ot em dewolla tfard eht morf deniag I deeps eht tub
.em diova ot elba eb ot tsaf oot hcum gnivom dna
.yaw fo tros gnidnecsednoc a ni ,dias feihc werc yM
,lortnoc niager ot delggurts I
.tnelis tnew reverof yehT
,avliS coruD naeS yb ”ecnahC dnoceS“
.em yfillom ot gnitpmetta saw eH
lortnoc niager ot tpmetta na ni htrof dna kcab leehw gnireets eht deknarc I sa eganrac elbativeni eht rof gnitiaw
tihsllub fo senil sseldne s’kciR ot gninetsil keew eritne eht dneps dna ,sgniteem ’srevird eht ,syad aidem eht ,slacisyhp eht
.klat pep a em evig dluow taht feihc werc decneirepxe na saw
.lla retfa learsI tuoba thgir saw I
tuo stcnitsni eht tel ot egru eht gnithgif
.taht od ot naht retteb nwonk ev’dluohs notfarC
.ria eht otni hcnual rac eht tlef dna
.reiksir dna rethgit saw ereh ecaps eht tub
.ylbissoP“       .deksa I
ezah yarg eht hguorht emac gnihtemos nehT
,rettam t’ndid ti ,nwod ro pu ,enil a esoohc ot dedeen learsI
.em fo tnorf ni nwod evid
.ti htiw emac taht mutnemom eht lla dna evoorg mottob eht tsol gnivah
”.dnim ni taht peek ll’I“
,tnemom feirb a rof dna ,syawedis rac ym detfihs evohs rehtonA
”,ereht nwod reh dloH
”.noitisop kcart taht otno dloh ot yrt ll’ew dna ni ’nimoc naelc ti peeK
,teg nac uoy tahw ekat ylpmis uoY
sevil yltnerruc dna dliuG ’sretirW yrruF eht fo rednuof eht saw eH .snikS tnereffiD
?kciR ,taht tuoba woH       .lleh ni yaw oN
mih gnihsup peeK
,og ot pal erom enO
.ruof nrut fo tuo gnidaeh em detfard pmub eh dna
”,enil eht ta spal ruoF“      .dik a tahT
elzzum ym tuhs tsuj I
.eson ym gninrub lio toh dna
.lwarc a ot dewols lla ti litnu yks ,dnuorg ,yks
.4 emuloV raoR ygolohtna eht ni derutaef yllanigiro
,dias ymmiJ ”,ay dniheb ’nimoc niart a s’ereht tub ’nivom s’rehtieN
,eerht nrut ni spmub eht ot emac ew sa deggep ydaerla dah enigne ehT
.evoorg mottob ro pot derovaf eht otni teg ot
.nwod su nar yeht erofeb sevoorg elbarovaf eht fo eno ot kcab teg ot dedeen ew tub
,tius erif eht rednu ykcits dna tew tlef ruf ym ,lleh naht rettoh saw tI
.gnikcerw morf ti evas ot rewop ym ni gnihtyreve gniod ,tuo rac eht nethgiarts ot htrof dna kcab leehw eht dekrej I
.eerf nur stcnitsni eht tel dna ,tnuh dna
,suonevar dna suoiciv
,detalitnevrepyh ylraen I
irt eht drawot evord rac xis-ytriht eht sa dehctaw I dna
.taes eht edisni dnuora em werht ti dna suorednuht saw tcapmi ehT
t’niA“       ”.ffo ’nihtemos nwolb evah ot
.krow ot og ot emit saw tI
.gninnips morf rac eht peek ot detnurg dna deniarts I sa
.nrut lanif eht neeb evah yam tahw drawot delttorht ew sa ria rof gnipsag
.dedaf gnihtyreve nehw s’tahT
,gnireehc erew yehT
”ecnahC dnoceS“   :yojne esaelP
ygolohtnA sdrawA ltoyoC eht ni derutaef
,evissergga erom gnitteg erew srecaR
,gniga na ,emit tsaL
,wol a ot nwod deteiuq enigne eht fo suocuar gnicreip eht dna
.enil hsinif/trats eht dessap ew sa gnivaw galf etihw eht eciton neve t’ndid I
.wol dna hgih puorg a toG“
.seiruxul dnik esoht dedroffa ton er’uoy em ekil enoemos ot semoc ti nehw sseug I
.leehw eht no gnittup neeb d’I niarts eht lla morf gninrub erew smra ym dna ,taes eht ni gnipmarc tpek liat ym
,dniheb teef wef a tsuj liat ym no toh erew yehT
,taht ekil tsuj dnA
”.pu ’niwolb tuoba denrecnoc
.sevoorg mottob dna pot eht ni sredael eht edisgnola pu gnillup ylisae
isaK deman revird rac ecar orp xe
taeh eht llems dluoc I
.sgnul rieht fo pot eht ta reehc dna
.selcsum eros ym otni seldeen mraw gnikcits saw enoemos fi sa tlef tI
ylthgils os reve ladep sag eht no pu tel ot dah I
,ecap eht pu dekcip eW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.edir s’learsI ot pu dekcus dna
,dik eht rof tpecxe rulb a saw gnihtyrevE .llet t’ndluoc I
gnihtemos ekam ot emit saw tI
dloH“ .temleh ym ni rekaeps eht hguorht laicifitra tsomla gnidnuos eciov sih
.temleh ym fo edisni eht tsniaga bur sreksihw ym gnileef
thgil emaceb I sa
.og lla ti tel ot emit saw tI
.ellezag gnieelf a fo sevooh eht ta epiws ot gnitpmetta erew I fi sa ,tib a wol tuc I
.enil wolley elbuod eht ot nwod tuc eh sa lenap kcab eht gnola gnidils rac enin-ytnewt eht leef dluoc I ,hcterts tnorf eht no lavo-irt eht hguorht erot ew sA
,esool dekciw emaceb rac yM
nwod ladep sag eht dehsup I sa dne revo dne gnippilf t’nsaw I dalg
…dworc eht fo raor suorednuht eht dna senigne eht fo dnuos gninefaed eht htiw gnola ,stcnitsni eht
.no tius siht htiw llet ot draH“
.leuf dna serit ruof rof ni emoc ,stip eht pu nepo yeht nehW“
”?pu ’nidloh ay woH“
.dleif eht flah kcerw ton dna
.pirg raer emos si deen I llA“
pirg ym fo tuo eerf nups leehw gnireets eht dna ,driht a neht
.niks ym rednu dnuora gnilwarc stcesni fo edroh a ekil
.dnuora tohsgnils ot deirt I fi tuo htob su ekat ro llaw eht otni mih nipS .mih llik ot gniog erew yehT
.nrut eht fo retnec eht ni spmub eht hguorht gnillor
.ynohpmys lacinahcem
,esoh ria eht revo deppirt nam kcaj eht nehw
,htaerb toh dna traeh gnidnuop sti raeh ylno dluoc I
.enin-ytriht eht fo dne raer eht gnidir
.yad eht ni kcab evird ot desu I selcihev eht ekil gnihton erew yehT
”,niaga elddim eht ni tuo gnuh em evael t’nseod su htiw og ot sediced reveohw erus ekam tsuj ,retteb hcuM“
;emoh kcab taht tog I
.rehsup eht rof tsaf oot toh oot teg senigne eht ,srac elyts rewen eseht htiw hguohT
.ssa ym ,eniF       ”.enif eb ll’uoY
,kcart eht pu klaw ot detnaw elcihev yM
dah uoY .yad eht fo pal tsetsaf ruoy nar tsuj uoY“       ”?yhW
.nrut tsrif eht drawot dedaeh ew sa
,tfel eht ot dekool I nehw dna ,ezad eht morf em derraj tI
.yzarc ekil gnignir erew srae ym esuaceb ,doG knahT .elbmur yrgna
”.mottob eht no ti dloh ot yrt tsuJ“
,esahc ot stcnitsni larutan sih htiw gnilaed elihw ,noititepmoc gnileurg tsom dna
.sey a htiw ti demrifnoc ymmiJ neht
.tuo delffuhs tog tsuj uoy ,saK ,nwod mlaC“       ”.doirep—
.nwonk reve dah trops ruo ecar tseggib eht now dratsab elttil ehT .ti did eH
.syawedis gnidils tnew rac ym dna ,nrut a ,hsup A
gninefaed a ekil selcihev rehto eht lla htiw nosinu ni efil ot deraor rac yM       .dewolleb ymmiJ
,pots ot elbanu ,em drawot gniltruh rac a—
,avliS coruD naeS yb ”ecnahC dnoceS“
pmuj dna elttar ot detrats rac ym sa ti leef dluoc I dna
.rac xis-ytriht s’learsI no
.sedis htob morf em ta emac dnuos gnilbmur tniaf a sa
.gniht nmad eht hcuot dna tuo hcaer dluoc I
.lla ti ot suoivilbo saw I dna
.enod tsomla er’uoy ,yrrow t’nod tub ,uoy tsuj s’tI“
,dnuorg eht neht ,yks eht was I
.em htiw hcuot ni teg esaelp
.t’ndluoc I tuB       ”.enil ruoy
ni deorez sucof ym sa gninekrad
.deef ot regnuh s’tcnitsni eht morf taes s’revird eht ni tuoba gnihsarht dna gnislup
,4-01“       ”.hsup ll’I me‘ lleT
.kcart eht htiw pirg tsol serit raer eht sa enihw dehctip hgih a tuo tel rotom eht dna
,pu dekcip deeps yM .emit ni tsuj tlahpsa eht deppirg yllanif serit ym
.rac nmad siht fo tuo teg ot saw
,sdlroW tnereffiD dna
ria eht hguorht tuc taht
,isaK ,thgir llA“       .em ykcuL
.ecnahc dnoces ym tog I tsael tA
.llits gnidnats saw I ekil drawrof gnideeps em woleb dna evoba srac fo niart eht gnihctaw ,stops lareves kcab deppord I
.tlahpsa eht ssorca gnidilg serit ym morf ekoms fo llaw a saw ees dluoc I lla
rentrap sih htiw saxeT ni
”.dne eht rof rentrap ’nicnad a uoy teg ll’I dna noitisop otni flesruoy teg uoY
.rettops tneced a saw ymmiJ tsael tA .elims ot dah I
”.isaK ,tnuoc me‘ ekaM“ .dias ymmiJ
.leehw gnireets eht no pirg ym denethgit I sa sevolg ym ni seloh gnikop ylraen ;tuo tohs swalc yM
,pu ecnamrofrep siht tpek ew fi dna ,oedor tsrif ym t’nsaw siht tub srae eht dniheb tew neeb evah yam notfarC
.kcab ecar tsrif ym ni
sdeeps eseht ta gninrut ekil t’ndid sniffoc esehT
.em gnitib morf god dliw a niartser ot gniyrt saw I ekil leehw eht gnippirg dna enil wolley elbuod eht raen ti gnidloh
sevolg eht hguorht decreip swalc ym sa revihs a tlef I dna ,hctiwt ot sdnah ym desuac tI
,tcapmi rehtonA
.srennur tnorf eht htiw pu hctac ot detrats ew sa stops fo elpuoc a kcab gnitteg
.skcirb ekil evord srac wen esehT
.pop dna kcarc ot ydob gniga ym fo strap lareves desuac dna
”!og ,og ,oG !galf neerg ,galf neerG
.ni delaid stcnitsni eht htiw toN .hguoht retsiger t’ndid tI
,yawa tnew kcart ecar ehT
sedisni ym ta gniwang stcnitsni eht gnileef
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.erew ydaerla yeht naht eromyna syug eht etavargga ot deen on was I
.resolc gnitteg em dniheb srac eht fo elbmur eht draeh I dna
”.ytlanep rehtona deen t’nod eW .deeps daor tip ruoy hctaw tsuJ
ladep sag eht esaeler ot tnaw t’ndid I
.ffo stcnitsni eht thgif ot deirt I sa gnilworg dna gnilrans ,leehw eht krej ot dah I
”,tser eht fo erac ekat nac I dna hcum taht em eviG
senal hctiws rac eerht-ythgie eht dehctaw I sa tnemom a rof taeb a deppiks traeh yM
,toh eerht nrut otni emac I
.stropsrotom ni tneve tseggib eht retne ot ecnahc dnoces a dereffo saw
.kcab emoc ot noisiced eht edam I nehw dnim ni dah I aedi eht yltcaxe toN
.dluoc I sa drah sa pil mottob ym tib dna ,ni devac I oS
.ni tuc rettops yM       ”—teg ew sa noos sa ,thgir llA“
yawhgih enal eerht repmub ot repmub
.mih ot noitnetta yap t’ndid I
”?ecar eht ni llits learsI sI“
dedeen I tahw tsuJ
er’yeht ,selim sulp 004 retfA
.tnemtsujda erusserp ria na htiw og dna pu uoy gninethgit yrt ll’eW
raor snaf eht ekam dluow taht eganrac yreif fo ezalb suoirolg a ni dleif eht flah pu gniraet dna enil ni rac eht gnipeek em neewteb doots taht lla s’taht ,sehcnI
.teef evitcelloc rieht ot esor dworc eht dna
.eromyna gnuoy t’nsaw I ,niaga neht tub ,emocrevo ot elbissopmi t’nsaw tahT .dedulcnoc
,yksir erom srevuenam eht
rac eht edisni em gnilttar
,dedworc a fo noisrev s’gnicar nwod gnirednuht erew ew hguoht neve ,llits gnidnats erew srac rehto eht fi sa dekool tI
”.tuo s’noituaC .tuo s’noituaC
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.od ot desoppus saw hateehc doog a ekil
.rettops sih htiw klaT“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,enil elddim siht attuo em teg ro ti xif attog syug uoY“
.esol ot gnihton dna niag ot gnihtyreve sah maet riehT
,eson ym tuo ylivaeh dehtaerb dna
tub thgirla saw I fi gniksa ,oidar eht revo em ta gnimaercs saw ymmiJ
.gnitaeb tnatsnoc eht morf ni evag yllanif egac llor eht erofeb erom ecno detfihs rac ym dna ,pop duol rehtona draeh I nehT
.gnitaolf saw I ekil tlef ti
.pu dexif uoy teg ll’eW“         .kcab dessih I
.stops ’nisol tuoba deirrow er’uoy fi enif eb dluow sedis thgiR
,em dnuora lla dneb dna
zonuM learsI was I nehw s’taht dnA
kcab emoc ot ecnahc eht rof pu derif em teG
,rac ym fo wodniw edis eht tuo reep ot elba saw I kcab yllanif sucof ym
.oidar eht revo dias ymmiJ
.evoorg reppu eht ni rac evif rebmun eht tsniaga gnimmals ylraen dne ssa eht
;ruoh na selim derdnuh owt revo ta esool pihw ot detrats rac eht dna
.nrut tsrif eht ot emac I sa oidar eht revo esuap feirb a saw erehT
eerf ylbidercni rac eht edam ria ssel taht noitnem ot toN
.ecar eht ni tniop siht ta noitnetnoc ni eb ot ykcul saw I
.tuo teg ot deniarts yeht sa
.leehw gnireets eht no pirg ym denethgit I dna
llaw eht otni gnimaercs kcerw delgnam a evird ot—
,sag eht no pu tel I
.ecar yreve retfa yldaed erom dna regnorts gnimoceb era hcihw llik dna ,tnuh
.lortnoc esol t’ndluow I os tsuj
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.lortnoc esol ot reisae hcum saw ti dna
wol nwod evid ot gniyrt fo daetsni mih devohs I os ,serit eht nups evah tsum eH .sdnatsdnarg niam eht fo tnorf ni enil eht dessorc ew sa rac eerht-ythgie eht pu delbbog ylraen I
.enil elddim eht ot kcab em ecrof dna edisni eht no nwod evid ot
.rehtie eguag eht ees t’ndluoc I tub strahc eht ffo ylbaborp saw erutarepmet ehT
”?regnol teg secar eseht did ro ,em tsuj ti sI“
mutnemom elbidercni htiw ruof nrut fo tuo gniraet
desucof yats tsuj ,ffo sleep rac ecap eht nehW“ .dias rettops ym
,reliops ym ffo ria gnikat erew sedis htob no srac ehT
,stcnitsni eht gnisu tuohtiw ,lleH
.deksa notfarC ”?leef ti s’woH“
,em evom ot detnaw eH
.oidar eht revo em ot tuo dellac rettops eht sa dehctiwt rae yM  2 fo 2 traP
em derraj llits ti ,ecarb kcen dna daeh dengised yllaiceps eht dna
noituac eht emit eht yb spal galf neerg neetriht ro evlewt htiw su evael ylbaborp dluow taht dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,og ot tfel spal neetfif revo tsuj htiw tops htneetriht eht ni saw I won os
nwod elttorht eht dednuop I       .neppah
.notfarC dah I dna
.tcaer t’ndid learsI tub
.tab llabesab a htiw ylsseltneler elcihev eht no gnitaeb saw enoemos ekil
tseggib s’eugael eht rof leehw eht dniheb pmuj ot tuoba si eh woN
ym htiw od ot gnihton gnivah saw em dniheb yug eht tub ,ni rac eht leer ot deirt I sa dleif eht fo tser eht ot derapmoc ruoh rep selim wef a deppord I
ti dniheb ylesolc os deliart I sa
.nepo s’daor tip ,thgirlA“
,pmub a tlef I nehT
.taht rof ereh tuo yaw eht lla emoc t’ndid I
.wor elddim eht ni deppart selcihev rehto eht htiw pu tem I sa
hsup lanif a ekam ot gniog erew ew fi deeps erom dedeen eW
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.pots tsal taht no serit owt tsael ta htiw tnew ev’dluohs uoY“
dna enog stcnitsni eht htiw
?kcab em thguorb kciR yhw taht
”?rac eht htiw gnorw s’tahW
,em emoceb dah rac eht fi sa saw tI
.dael eht koot dna srac rehto eht fo tnorf ni tsuj tuo dekeep ew sa
seirots dah osla eH
,sucof ylerab dluoc I
gnihsinif ta lleh ni ecnahc a evah annog t’nia ew ,esiwrehto
pu mih gniwols elcihev esool
.evoorg reppu eht ni weiv ym morf raeppasid rac evif rebmun eht dehctaw I dna
.erom hcum ekat t’ndluow enigne ehT
,nwod rac eht decrof I sa tnurg a htiw dias I ”.tsaf saw I esuaC
.owt nrut ni llaw eht dekcams tsuj rac eniN
dedeen yllaer I tahW
.srevird tsil C eht htiw
,enil eht no tuo gnihtyreve evael dna elttorht lluf evird oT .emit lanif eno
,delbmurg dna daeh ym koohs I
tub egakcerw eht hguorht ezeeuqs ot elba neeb evah yam yehT
.won su fo thgir dna tfel eht ot tfard edis a dah eW
”.srenroc eht ni gnitfard pmub eht lla htiw ti otno dloh ylerab nac I dna eerf nmad oot m’I won esuaC
.ffo s’rac ecaP .isaK
.wohs ot gninnigeb saw ecar gnol eht fo yteixna ehT
.nac uoy sa stops ynam sa ffo kcip dna
.hsinif ytnewt pot a htiw yawa emoc ot ykcul eb d’ew
,ffo koot dna kcap elddim eht morf detarapes su fo owt ehT .efink a ekil
,tif doog a eb dluow kniht uoy taht yrots a evah uoy fi dnA
,lenap raer sih rednu dekcut rac ym fo eson ehT
.ti rof tiaW .ydaetS“
tius wollof dna em ees dluow eh gnipoh ,dik eht dniheb thgit pu dekcut llits saw I
.em dnuora lla gnimaercs senigne eht potrevo mih raeh ylerab dluoc I tey
.uoy morf raeh ot evol d’I dna
,esuap trohs a saw erehT
.oidar eht revo gnimoc dnuos delffum a draeh I nehw s’taht dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.dniheb morf deggat tog I nehw elttil a deppihw elcihev eht fo dne raer eht sa deilper I
rac xis-ytriht eht llik ot tsul larecsiv taht
seippup suoremun dna
,dnoces tilps a roF
”,htiw nur ot ydobemos uoy gnitteg no ’nikrow m’I
”?sriap ni gninnur yrt ot gnilliw ydobynA“
.mih htiw esolc yats ot dah I
”!gniht nmad siht kcerw annog m’I“
,oot elyts ni lla ti did I dnA
,oidar eht revo tuo dellac ymmiJ ”,og ot spal neT“      .ssatramS
.lavo-irt eht rof gnidaeh hctertskcab eht nwod selcihev rehto eht desahc dna
gniK eht eb dluoc I oS
,gnimoc erew yehT .edepmats ehT
.timil deeps detsop eht semit eerht tsomla ta
,thgir tsuj ti demit I
.temleh ym ni gniohce eciov sih ,deksa notfarC
.ay dniheb ’nikcerw er’yehT“
.oidar eht revo detuohs I
”.laed a uoy krow ll’I dna kcart eht no seye ruoy peeK
,suoiruf a ekil dednuos eW
.dniheb shtgnel rac lareves srelggarts wef a htiw lavo-
,lortnoc fo tuo elbmut ot gniunitnoc rac eht morf noisiv ym epolevne
.dniheb morf pmub a tlef I litnu
.eerf kaerb t’ndluow stcnitsni eht ,did I tahw rettam on dna
latem teehs delgnam dna ekoms ,sirbed erom was I sa dnA