.sniap eht dna sehca eht llA
.thgiarts kniht neve ro
?si ereht seires gnicar evititepmoc tsom ,tseggib eht ni
.reliart eht fo sllaw eht hguorht gnicreip draeh I eciov delffum sih gnieb pu dedne ti
dliuG ’sretirW yrruF eht fo rednuof eht saw eH
.meht detah I ,yaw a nI
.kcart eht ta tneps sraey eseht lla retfa tohs hcum ytterp saw gniraeh yM
em wonk t’nod uoy esuaceb s’tahT“
pal retfa pal gninrut morf rebbur fo sekalf ynit dna tsud eht htiw gnola ,dne no syad rof slirtson ruoy edisni eht ot deulg hcnets tnegnup tahT
,weiv fo dleif ym otni dekcol saw owt-
?ffo kcab ti hctiws ot em rof tluciffid erom dna erom gnimoceb saw ti
htaenrednu yltcerid em htiw ,owt nrut fo tuo gnimoc yltcefrep pu mih tes dah I .detiaw I tub
hguone gnol tsuj esuap oT .pots ot dah I
,dnuora yats ot gnithgif saw tI
.mih rewsna ot evah neve t’ndid I yhw saw hcihw
nrut yllanif ot rood ym fo tnorf ni nam gnidlab
.ecap eht pu dekcip dna shgiht ym otni gud sregnif reh elihw riah eht gnilkcit
,aidem eht htiw klat ot ytilibisnopser a dah I
”?elyK ot deneppah tahW
”?ti taht sI .elyK rof revo ekat dna pu kcab tius ot em tnaw uoy …sseug em tel oS“
.hcaeB avoniaD ta
,ereht saw I wenk eH
.namwoB .J.C ,noipmahc seires gningier ,emit-2 eht dna namsirhC odnalrO htiw gnola thgir ,dellik tog dik eht tub ,erofeb sraeY .emit ym erofeb neeb lla dah ti ,naem I
”,neht saw taht ,llew …haeY“
.lortnoc emos kcab em evag yllanif edis lamina eht nehw s’tahT
trats dna taes eht otni flesym elkcub
.dekrow ev’dluow reven erovibreh nA“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,reliart ym fo ytitcnas eht ot kcab teg ot saw
.mih dah I dna owt ro pal rehtona
,uoy rof taht od nac yenoM
.dniheb tfel gnitteg saw I dna ,nwo rieht lla efil a no gnikat erew stcnitsni ehT
”.elpmis dna nialp ,tsif revo dnah
.ti dekil reven I .taht em gnillac tiuQ“
.dne on ot tuo em gnisserts fo yaw a dah stcnitsni ehT
nepo rood eht dehsup ehs nehT
meht ot rats kcor a ekil si dik ehT
”?tog uoy kniht uoy od regnol hcum woH“        .deddon I
,detnaw I fi won thgir ti od dluoc I
.trap tsrow eht raf yb saw ti ,esion eht tuB
.sgnir trid ,yhtlif eseht dnuora
.evren a kcurts tahT
,dlrow siht morf yawa gnidaf saw I ekil leef em edam tI
”.setunim net tuoba ni kcab emoC .emit doog a ton yllaer s’woN“
.reerac eritne ruoy dna
saw htiw laed ot dah srotitepmoc namuh ym evitanretla eht enigami I hguohT
,detuohs I os ,deunitnoc gnikconk ehT       .krow t’ndid tI
.koob tekcop ruoy si uoy ot tnatropmi gniht ylno ehT“
.enilosag dna lio tnrub fo tnecs suoixon eht ffo gnivig dna gnimuf senigne rieht htiw
.splug egral lareves ni nwod ti gnigguhc dehsinif dna
.ylrae oot sorp eht otni mih dehsup dna
.swen lacol eht no sevlesmeht rof noitnetta niag ot redro ni elbbird sseldnim detuops ohw
.trac flog a fo tuo gnillaf redluohs sih ekorb elyK yob ytterp woh gniraeh ynnuf adnik saw ti ,timda ot evah I hguohT
.tluciffid sgniht gnikam s’ti …s’ti ,nwodkaerb ehT
.ti od ot yaw eno ylno saw ereht sseuG
.smra htob dehctertstuo I sa dias I
.lanif s’thginot otni
.trops eritne eht deyortsed ylraen tI
.srallod ’a snoillim nopu snoillim ni sekar eh dna
”.seires rewol a morf enoemos barg uoy tseggus I nehT“
”?ydaerla dab taht s’tI“
.mih eb ot dah ti
.evohs elttil a mih evig ,retteb neve ro
.mih dniheb rood eht esolc ot erus gnikam
,tnaw uoy revetahW“
”?ereht tuo em tnaw llits uoy ,nwodkaerb eht tuoba uoy dlot I tahw retfa nevE“ .s’kciR tem ot
.won ti otni erom gnitteg reh tlef I
.tnedicca yb ffo stcnitsni eht tes t’ndid I os
.elihw a rof ni thguoht taht kaos mih teL
,yldetniop dias I ”,kciR ,yawa oG“
,denwod a no egacbir eht nepo gnippop ekil
neppah lla dluow ti dnA
”.aedi dab a erew stnemanruot flog ytirbelec esoht thguoht syawla I
,seeb lacinahcem fo mraws yrgna na ekil dednuos meht fo eno hcae dna ,enola taeh tsrif eht ni sniffoc latem neT
”.lliw ohw ydobemos em dnif attog I
.sedir s’kciR fo eno ni
.reliart eht fo ecnartne eht drawot gnitniop
droffa ot elba eb neve t’ndluow uoy ,em rof t’nerew ti fI“
.ytivitpac ni tfel os ro neetfif eht rof tpecxe ,won tcnitxe yllacitcarp erew shateehc gniK
er’yehT .srac eht tsuj no sucof t’ndluoc yeht dnA“ .daeh ym koohs I
?pu saw tcartnoc ym sa noos sa
”.evah uoy slliks eht tog me‘ fo enon t’nia dna
.owt dna eno snrut hguorht edils eht detrats ew sa thgir eht ot kcab naht tfel ti gniknarc
,RCSA eht ni kcab saw tI .ereh t’nsaw tI
a …os ,emit hcae esrow gnitteg s’tI .wonk t’nod I“
.elbaraebnu thgir nwod emaceb ti ,sgniht eseht fo eno edisnI
”.esle enoyna ro uoy rof loot nmad a t’nia I ,uoy dlot ydaerla I“       ”.si ti tahw ro
.kciR rof wohs eht etiuq eb ot dah ti denigami I
teef sih tnalp dluow rotaderp a woh ekil hcum
.rac elyts rewen eht htiw detniauqca flesruoy teG
.sruoh thgiarts eerht rof selcric tcefrep ylraen ni evord tsuj yeht dna
,ecar yreve erofeb sruoh sulp eerht rof shtuom rieht nur yeht nehw tihs taht fo hguone od srecnuonna ehT
knuf elttil rieht attuo teg dluoc yeht os tsuJ
,avliS coruD naeS yb ”ecnahC dnoceS“
.retupmoc a otni sgniht esoht margorp t’nac uoY
,yawa dedaf lla yeht ;swas zzub dehctip-hgih ekil dednuos taht selcihev degniw elttil eht lla dna ,kcart eht
mih fo tnorf ni pu dezeeuqs I dna
”.uoy ezingocer neve ylerab d’I teb I
tseebedliw a fo teef eht tuo gnikat ekil ,ysae mih lliK
”?gnorw neeb reve I evaH“       ”?tcaf a tahT“
seippup suoremun dna
”.rehtie mih emalb I yas t’naC
daeh sih koohs tsuj kciR
.tnereffid erew uoy …uoy tuB
.snikS tnereffiD ,sdlroW tnereffiD dna
,dlrow eht ni elpoep eht lla fO
”,ssob ,ti evah uoy ereh ,lleW
.niaga ecar em tel reven d’yehT
.yad siht ot neve ,evila kciR tae ot deunitnoc noisiced taht teb I
.enil hsinif/trats eht ot hcterts tnorf eht nwod erot ew sa
,skcart eht ot emoc ot elpoep teg ylerab dluoc ew ,thgir dna tfel tuo gnillup srosnops eht dna ,sserp dab eht ,stiuswal eht lla neewteB
.egakcerw delgnam ,gnikoms taht fo tuo dellup yeht dik ym neeb dah ti fi ,em dluow tI
.no kcab trihs reh gnittup delggurts dna dleifni eht nwod edorts ehs sa ednolb sselpot eht ta gnirats
.ehca ot nageb selcsum ym lla sa htaerb rof pu drah ,gnipsag saw I
.em ot ezag sih denruter yllanif eh nehw dias kciR
.tlah gnihceercs a ot emac gnihtyreve dna ,rood eht ta kconk a saw ereht nehT
tilps I kniht uoy od yhW“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ti naem I dna ,on dias I“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
evod I eerht nrut ot emac ew sa dna
?eil ,od ot desoppus I saw tahW .ereht em dah hctib-a-fo-nos ehT .parC
stcnitsni eht edaM
.uoy t’nia siht dna
.gnihtyreve ,snoisses aidem eht ,gnitomorp eht ,noitnetta eht lla
?srevird rehto eht llik ot tnaw em edam ti
tuhs demmals reliart ym ot rood eht ,hsinif dluoc I erofeB       ”—ton m’I
.mih ot txen pu thgir llup ot erus edam dna owt-
.owt-ytnewt rebmun dna em tsuj saw ti neht dna
.smurd rae degamad eht morf niarb ym edisni gnilttar romalc tnatsnoc eht dna stnioj ym ni sehca eht dehtoos taht gniht emas eht gnieb pu dedne tI
,ton ro ti eveileb uoy rehtehw dnA
”.ecar eht morf gnignir llits era srae yM .kciR ,pu kaeps ot deen uoY“
”.did uoy ytinutroppo eht evah ot mra thgir rieht nevig ev’dluow srevird esoht fo eno yna tub ,secnatsmucric etanutrofnu
”?snoitaitogen tcartnoc laitini eht gnirud siht lla tuoba uoy llet yeht t’ndiD
,edisni em dewollof kciR dna riahc ym ot kcab derutnev tsuj I
.ruf ym fo tser eht dettod taht
no sesnes eht denrut I emit yreve taht meht ot nialpxe I dluow woH .lleh ni yaw on
won saw rof detaerc neeb d’I gnihtyreve dna
”.won thgir tiucric eht no tuo srevird eht fo tsom naht
,efil sih fo kcabemoc tseggib
.won ti tuoba kniht t’ndluoc I tuB
.nwod gnihtemos gnisahc elihw ffo hsup dna
”?loohcs gnidaelreehC ?syadawon srevird eseht gnitteg uoy lleh eht erehw ,em llet oS“
,avliS coruD naeS yb ”ecnahC dnoceS“
”.on llits s’rewsna ehT“
?huh ,gnihtemos ro ellezag a ro arbez a otni uoy ekam t’ndid yeht dab ooT“
”.zonuM learsI sa tnelat hcum sa flah evah t’nod eh ,sediseb dnA
.noonretfa taht sdnatsdnarg eht otni deppilf dna ecnef hctac eht hguorht ekorb srac rieht nehw derujni erew ohw snaf rehto sseltnuoc eht dna srotatceps emos noitnem ot toN
,niap eht ekat ot raeb t’ndluoc I litnu ro ,ecar txen eht litnu tnuh ot deen t’ndluow I
,arbez a ekil dekool fo dnik elop eht no gnittis rac ehT
,tnereffid erom neve leef em edam tI
eht hguorht ti ekam ot hguone gnol stcnitsni sih lortnoc nac isaK fi tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
t’noD“       ”.ti llac uoy sa ,ffuts tna ssip emit llams eht ’ninnur ,ereh tog I tahw ekil I ,yllanosrep dnA
.yllautneve em ot od ot gniog ylbaborp erew yeht tahw dna
.taht wenk I ,suoregnad dna hsifles saw tI
.lortnoc rednu meht gnipeek …kciR ,elbuort gnivah m’I“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
sruetama eseht dnuora selcric gninnur
,ilihawS ni gninaem sah yllautca eman ehT .isaK s’tI
,won yromem morf lla saw tI
”,od attog uoy tahw od uoy
.retnuoc nehctik eht ffo gnihtyreve tuoba tsuj gnikconk pu dedne gniht eht esuaceb ,dessim ehs dab ooT
hteet ym htiw ti gnittuc
.dluow meht fo tol a gnitteb m’I“
,noisnet on ,zzazzip on saw erehT
”.sdnats eht otni enola tel
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.etar siht ta syad fo elpuoc a naht erom eb t’ndluow hcihw
.yldaed erom …reraelc ,reprahs
.ellezag dekcinap a fo knalf eht otni gniguog ro
egats tseggib eht no
”?siht ekil gnieb yppah er’uoy taht flesruoy llet neve uoy nac woH
.hcaeB avoniaD si ereh eussi niam eht tuB
.yawyna ,trap lacisyhp ehT
.doolb fo gnat prahs taht rof egru eht deef dluoc I os tsuj
.isaK ,rood eht nepO“
.pu ti kool ot derehtob reve uoy fi ,si taht
”.drazil a ro ,mrof siht rehtie saw ti ,dnatsrednu I tahw morf ,kceH .hsittiks oot
.tnatculer elttil a demees ti hguoht ,deddon kciR
,swap ykahs owt htiw reeb ym dehctulc dna
.ysae emaceb ti nehT
.llaw edistuo eht otni thgiarts gnidaeh
;stcnitsni eht tuoba wonk noitaicossa eht tel reven dluoc I tuB
.secar eerht ro owt naht erom eb t’ndluohs taht dnA .pu slaeh eh litnu tsuJ“
,em ot gniod erew yeht tahw gnidulcni ,oga gnol meht tuoba wenk eH
.ti hguorht thgir ees dluoc eH
.reklaW ybboB gnuoy tuoba nettogrof tsomla dah I .suseJ
,ruf ym tsniaga desserp htaerb toh reH
,sseccus ruoy lla
.lortnoc ekat ot stcnitsni eht rof reisae hcum taht ti ekam saw did elcihev eht llA
”.eromyna egats gib eht no tuo gnoleb t’nod I
reerac s’yob eht trats pmuj ot detnaw ylbaborp eh ,kciR gniwonk tuB
tnelaviuqe na tnaw yeht oS
ecno ti dias I“
.ti fo trap s’tahT“
,skool ruoy rof t’nsaw ti fi ,kceH
?huh ,ni emac I erehw s’taht dnA“
?taht ees uoy t’noD
,ecar yreve no ti nrut t’nod I fi nosaes lluf a llup dluoc I ytilibissop a s’erehT
”.em no ythgim dna hgih lla teg uoy erofeb taht rebmemer tsuj uoY
.esle gnihtyna ro yhtapmys naht tsugsid fo tuo erom saw ti tub ,taht ta dehgual kciR
.gnihton ,tniap ’nidart on ,tcilfnoc revird on
,ti tuoba kniht uoy nehw dnA
,esac eht saw taht fI“       ”.RCSA eht ro
.uoy rof tnaem neve t’nsaw ,ti fo tib yreve
,dias I ”,ereht thgir s’rood ehT .ssob ,daeh ruoy ot nug a ’nidloh t’nia I“
.su neewteb ecaps emos teg dluoc I os sag eht ffo gnisae ,wol
,gniht eno ylno rof doog saw I woh em gnidnimer tpek yehT
”.tsixe neve I yhw
.rehtie ,saK em llac t’nod dnA
,ev’dluow esle ydobemos ,ti od t’ndid I fi dnA
.hteet latem gnivigrofnu esoht ni ruf hcum woh swonk doG deggans I esuaceb gnicamirg dna stnap ym pu gnippiz dehsinif I emit eht tuoba thgir ,rood eht ot delbmuts I yllautnevE
.tekcop kcab sih ni pu denil srosnops deman gib eht lla sah dna
”.tnirp enif eht daer dluoc
…selcihev detarepo yletomer
ecar nmad eht now dna enil hsinif eht dessorc dah I eciton neve t’ndid I ,kceH
,dnuora gnilbmuts em neewteB
”.pu taht dewercs ydaerla uoy dna ,kniht ot emit deen I
.riahc eht tsniaga kcab llaf daeh ym tel I sa rrup laruttug
.edisa nac ytpme na gnissot elihw dedda I
,ygdup eht gnicrof
.ekaw reh ni tfel rekooh sselpot ssiM elttil noitcurtsed eht ta kool ot tnemom a gnikat
,si ti revetahw esuaC .klat—thgirlA“
,dluow eh derugif I ekil ,dessap kciR nehW
.nepo ti deppop dna rehtona rof dehcaer ylkciuq I
.ecar yreve dna hcae retfa dna erofeb detset eb ot dah I taht erac t’ndid RCSA ehT
.emehcs tniap straP otuA pihsnoipmahC etihw dna kcalb yknuf taht htiw
hctiwt elcsum keehc tfel sih dehctaw I sa ecaf s’kciR ni ti ees dluoc I
.etunim a tsuj no gnah woN“       ”.tsol teg oS
.htiw revo tihsesroh yppah siht lla teg dna
.esrow yna kool ecalp eht ekam dluoc ehs fi sA
”.reliart ym dna em morf yawa lleh eht teg ot uoy tnaw I yhw s’taht dnA
.ekahs ot detrats sdnah ym sa ti wonk em tel yeht dna yrgnuh erew stcnitsni ehT
evah ll’I“ .rood eht rof gnidaeh detrats dna pu tog eh sa dias kciR ”,eniF“
.daed mih detnaw yehT
.isaK ,sloot lla er’eW“
.yerp ym evah d’I tub ,I dluow os dna ,elpmurc d’eH
”.smelborp eseht lla gnivah eb t’ndluow uoy ebyaM
.no kcab trihs nmad reh tup dna rekooh a ekil gnikool pots ot reh dlot I nehw lufroloc erom neve tog egaugnal ehT
.ysnap a llits s’eh ,ti ta kool uoy yaw rehtiE“
.flesym rof eno debbarg dna riahc ym ot txen tsehc eci eht otni nwod dehcaer I
.em ot kcab sucof reh gnitfihs erofeb reliart eht fo ecnartne eht ta deralg dna daeh reh detfil ehS
.otni hteet ym knis yllaer dluoc I noititepmoc reffits dna
ekahs elttil a daeh ym gnivig neve
.yrtsudni ytilitu eht ni reerac sih no gnisucof elihw
.eno taht ta elkcuhc ot dah I
.enal sih otni pu hsup ot gniog saw rac yM
.ssih gniyfsitas taht ni ekat dluoc I os nepo nac reeb eht gnippop
regnad erom htiw ,egnellahc A
.taht od dluoc I ecalp eno ylno saw ereht dna
,delworg dna semit wef a seye ym deknilb I
.traeh a dah llits ssob eht ees ot dooG
.emit a ta pal eno
”.reffo ot sah ecneics revird rac ecar gnitaroireted yllaciteneg dna pu dehsaw ,tseb ehT“
.reffo ot sah gnicar
,em htiw tsael ta tuB .ton ylbaborP“
”?em tuoba nmad a evag reve RCSA eht kniht uoy oD .em llet uoy oS
.nwo rieht lla dnim a evah ot gninnigeb erew stcnitsni eht ebyaM
.mih htiw sllip traeh sih gnirb ot thguoht ev’dluohs kciR sseuG .lortnoc rednu erusserp doolb sih teg pleh ot ylbaborp ,semit lareves ylpeed ehtaerb dna seye sih bur ot dah eH
sah yug ehT ?learsI“
”.ekil dekool uoy tahw fo sseldrager ,uoy devol aidem eht dna snaf ehT
.doog saw ehs ,nmaD
.dnuora sllor yadirF nehw ecitcarp rof ydaer eb ll’uoy ,yaw tahT
.tiucric lanoisseforp eht no nosaes lluf a ni kcolc ot ecnahc a dah neve eh erofeb nwod tuc tog eh dna
,lworg a htiw deksa I ”?reeb a tnaw uoY“
.ti gninaem yllaer ton
”,dnekeew tsal elyK ot deneppah tahw tuoba draeh ev’uoy gnisseug m’I nehT“
,taht wenk htob eW
.eromyna no pirg a teg t’ndluoc I efil ym fo trap eht saw taht dnA
…revo ekat stcnitsni eht
.thginot dirg lluf a eb dluow erehT  2 fo 1 traP ,avliS coruD naeS yb
”.revetahw ,yllatnem ,yllacisyhp uoy ot neppah ot gniog saw tahw fo sseldrager
nur dna tuo og ot ytinutroppo ehT
.ti draeh I emit yreve hgual em edam tI
,hcum ekat t’ndluow tI
.seires depmaver ,wen sih raen erehwyna ssa deriter ym ees ot tnaw t’nseod sicnarF yob ynneK ’lo doog uoy teb I dnA“ .reeb paehc rehtona kcab gniworht erofeb dias isaK
.htiw laed ot lufniap erom ,redrah tog ti ,yadyrevE
uoy edam ecar tahT
.gniht a raeh t’ndluoc I dna yltfos deklat neve ro em ot derepsihw uoY
.noitcerid ym ni regnif gnilbmert won
.htamretfa eht dna yaD-D rof dnuora t’nerew uoy ,gniyas saw I sA“
snaf eht dna sthgil eht htiw laed dna rac eht fo tuo teg ot emit saw tI
”.noitcartta wohsedis nmad doG emos ekil—yot wen etirovaf s’tiucric ehT
,dne eht ni ,llew …kciR dnA
.yaD-D rof t’nsaw ti fi ereh ecar ot elba eb neve t’ndluow uoY .efil elohw ruoY
.erit raer sih fo teef wef a nihtiw gnisolc
.esle gnihtyreve deirt ydaerla dah yehT
ohw fo sseldrager—
?ecnahc dnoces a uoy gnivig m’I nehw tor dna reliart siht ni tis tsuj annog uoy erA ?tahw neht ,siht ton fi dnA“
srac eht snwo yddad ruoy nehw yllaicepse
,sweivretni eht lla detah I
.sesnes eht gninethgieh fo yaw a dah tI
.mhtyhr fo tuo ydob ym ecrof ot deirt I sa
,deilper I ”,tahwemoS“
.ecar ot edam ylpmis saw I esuaceB ?yhw dna—oN
.nosaes 42‘ eht tuoba rehtomdnarg rieht dna enoyreve gnillet tuohtiw raey eno og ot mees t’nac yeht dna
yenom ni gnikar trats dna
eh llA .dleif eht fo tser eht revo egatnavda fo tros emos evah t’ndid I
,leehw eht dniheb tnelat eurt A
!dellik elpoep fo tol a gnitteg pu dne ll’I tahT“
eno 005 eht trats ot ecnahc eht rof sevlesmeht revo ’nippirt eb dluow srevird deriter ynam woh ezilaer uoy oD .isaK ,tsirhC fo evol eht roF“
.kcufretsulc a saw tI“
,redlo tog I sa taht meht dlot I fi tahw dnA .lamina dednuow
,erit tnorf thgir a nwolb dah I ekiL
ygolohtnA sdrawA ltoyoC eht ni derutaef seirots dah osla eH
”.ysae ,pihsnoipmahc a dna sniw evif uoy teg ll’eh dna
.os ro ruoh rehtona rof tsael ta ,enod eb d’I
.gniunitnoc erofeb hgis duol a tuo tel kciR       ”.pu
,taes sih ni drawrof denael dna
.evila emoc ot detrats em fo edisni lamina laref
.evom a ekam ot ydaer gnitteg arbez dekcinap a ekil tsuj
,slortnoc gnizilibats htiw srac
.dengis eb annog erew uoy ,rehtona ro yaw enO .tiucric eht otni gnitteg erew uoY
.sepirts gnicar ni tliub htiw revird a etaerc ot edoc citeneg eht gnisu
em gnidnimer speek ti taht noitnem ot toN
edir tneced a ni mih teg ,revo si tcartnoc sih nehw pu mih kcip uoY
,rac owt-ytnewt rebmun eht fo lenap raer eht no ni desucof I nehW
.sdoow eht fo txen ym ot tuo yaw eht lla uoy gnirb ot doog eb attog s’ti
.od ot desoppus saw hateehc doog a ekil ,yerp ym gniklats
.stcnitsni eht tuoba wenk kciR
hsart reliart fo eceip teews ym dna no stnap ym tup ot tnew I sa
”,dik doog a s’elyK ,ton ro edutitta sih ekil uoy rehtehW“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.reeb ym ta nwod gnirats tpek tub ,deddon I        ”?draziL“
,sleer thgilhgih dna soediv dlo eht ta kcab gnikool ,nees d’I tahw morf dnA
eerht ni snet pot owt …tahw ,ebyam
.erom gnihtemos rof nraey em edam sdeeps wols eht woh dna
.taht lla dna lartneC stropS teg od I“
,yletaidemmi tsomla tuo emac erans suoiciv ehT
gnidaeh taeh tsrif eht ekat d’I dna pal erom eno ,ti saw siht tuB
.rac ecar a gnivird
.wodniw nmad eht tuo thgir emaf dna sseccus ruoy lla worht dluoc uoy ecar taht rof t’nsaw ti fI“
.on si rewsna eht
xaler ot dedeen ehs reh dlot I esuaceb sgnul reh fo pot eht ta gnirelloh ,tif noitpinnoc a gnivah
.htuom ym otni delkcirt doolb fo liart niht a sa
,ti evah dluow kcul sa dnA
,mub a ekil ’nivil er’uoY
elttorht eht ffo tel owt-ytnewt os ,enil derreferp eht dah I
,ynnuf eb dluow ti thguoht
ytnewt ylno esuaceb ,kcart eht no erew srevird rehto eht erehw ees neve t’ndluoc I
reeb ym desiar I
,yteicos namuh ni erar I saw ylno ton taht em dednimer dna
.yob ym—ot enog ev’dluohs tI
”.aedi doog ytterp a evah ydaerla I dnA
.em detaerc yeht nehw taht tuoba kniht yeht did tuB
.emankcin taht detah syawla I
”.ffo meht nrut ot redrah dna redrah gnitteg s’ti
”?ti eldnah nac uoy kniht llits uoY“
.syawla sa yssalC
”?huh ,rehtie enil mottob ruoy truh t’ndid RCSA eht morf tog uoy gnikcab laicnanif artxe taht lla teb ot gnilliw m’I tub ,os ebyaM“
.4 emuloV raoR ygolohtna eht ni derutaef yllanigiro
”.tnatropmi s’tI .eno siht no tuo em raeh ot uoy deen I
.yrgnuh erew stcnitsni eht ,llitS
.em htiw tcatnoc eye ekam dna
”…noitpecrep htped fo kcal rieht htiw tub ,erus ,weiv fo dleif ediw a evah yehT
.gninrom eht ni llac a uoy evig yorlEcM
”—ym ot enog ev’dluohs ti esuaC
”.llet ot yaw on s’ereht …tub
.erofeb deklat dna deklaw taht hateehc a nees reven d’eh ekil em ta gniralg
.etteragic rehtona evah dna
?uoy ot deneppah lleh eht tahW“
.ezilaer ylbissop dluoc ehs naht eroM
.em fo dloh tpek ti tub—tcnitsni eht ffo koohs ti sa gnol sa tsuj ,gnihtynA
,tey dnA        .esrow hcum ,hcum
.raeppasid ot demees esle gnihtyreve
.esrow gnitteg saw tI
,ereht llits saw kciR yletanutrofnU
ohw enO .neht reywal retteb a dah ev’dluohs uoy sseuG“
,rorrim eht ni thgir tsuj denrut I fI .neht dna won yreve meht ees dluoc I
.noitautis s’ynapmoc eht fo ytireves eht ezilaer dna tnemom a ekat ot evah uoY“
denoitseuq dna deweivretni ,debbaj ,deddorp ,dekop gnieb em tnaem taht fi neve
”.gnipleh eb t’nac stibah gniknird ruoY“
”?eromyna erac ton tsuj uoy oD“
.ti detah snaf ehT
,trid eht ,dworc ehT
.eman a deen I dna pu dekcol ydaerla era seno doog ehT“
,ybbuts a detniop eh sa yltpurba gnidne ecnetnes sih
.elyK rof ni llif ot eman gib a tnaw srosnops eht dnA .sklat yenoM“
,peed a htiw dnopser em edam ti dnA
,nrub stcnitsni eht ekam dluow taht gnihtemos dedeen I
.yas syawla dluow snamuh eht sa ,sgge wef a kaerb ot tog ev’uoY
”.htiw deifsitas eb lliw srosnops eht enoemoS
,ti erongi ot deirt dna riah ednolb ,gnol s’namow eht hguorht dnah dewalc ym nar tsuj I os ,gnimit dab saw ti ,yaw rehtiE
rentrap sih htiw saxeT ni sevil yltnerruc dna
.noitasrevnoc tnegru naht tnatropmi erom sgniht emos erew ereht sseug I
.revird rehto yna naht erom
taes eht ni revo dehcnuh I
?rettam eht ni eciohc a dah I kniht uoY“
.ruoh na naht ssel ni taeh lanif eht rof ydaer teg attog I esuaC ?enod uoy erA“
.eerht nrut ni llaw eht no ngis liO llehctiM eht rof thgiarts mia dna
”?gniK ,rebmemer uoy t’nod ,suomaf emoceb uoy nehw neppah sgnihT“
.nwodkaerb si rehto ehT
.esuap ot nrut ym saw ti derugif I os ,dnopser t’ndid eH
”.syad eseht rorrim eht ni kool I nehw fles nwo ym ezingocer neve t’nod I
,kcab sih ffo aidem eht gnitteg saw tuoba derac
…fo tol a hguorht og ot dah evah yam uoY
.enal tip ni llits dnats a ta erew srotitepmoc rehto eht was I retfa litnu
.llew sa eno lamina eht ni tub
,uoy htiw od ot gnihtyna tnaw t’nod I dna
.diputs yllaer gnihtemos did I erofeb ffo nrub ot emit stcnitsni ym evig dna
.rac eht edisni taeh eht eldnah ot detius retteb eb dluow elitper a thguoht yeht yltnerappA“
erus ekam dluoc noititepmoc fo rotcerid eht os tsuJ
,srac ym fo eno dereffo erew yeht fi enola teL ?emit tsal
setunim wef a rof tnelis llef reliart ehT
,kciR ,emit eht flaH“
,trapa meht pir dna segac latem rieht otni raet ot tnaw em edaM
.esruoc eht no esle enoyreve rof tub ,em rof ylno ton—suoregnad saw taht dna
.yub dluoc yenom lennosrep dna tnempiuqe tseb eht dah uoy
?siht evresed ot od I did lleh eht ni tahw ,nmaD .reklaW kciR
”?fo diarfa os uoy era lleh eht tahw ,naem I
,won ti etsat dluoc I
?dnekeew tsal tuoba draeh uoy gnisseug m’I ,dias I“
.oge kciht sih dna kciR ot emac ti nehw yllaicepse ,thgir gnieb devol I
”.llacer nac I taht toN .oN“
.tnempiuqe yttihs htiw maet dab a no s’eH“       ”.sraey
.stiucric emid dna lekcin ,tna ssip elttil eseht ni gnicar
”.draobno llits er’uoy fi pohs eht ot tuo ylf ot uoy rof stnemegnarra ekaM
detiaw ev’dluoc eH
”.hcum taht em ewo uoY
”…os ,sdeeps hgih eht htiw gnilaed fo eussi eht sserdda ot tnatropmi erom saw ti derugif yeht ,dne eht ni tuB
.thgiew s’kciR tsniaga kaerc pets latem eht draeh I dna
”ecnahC dnoceS“   :yojne esaelP
.em ta yhport seires liO llehctiM ym gniworht pu dedne ehs os ,ffo reh dessip tahT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
tel dna ,no ti—nrut I nehW
.semitemos tnew gnitnuh yaw eht saw taht tub ,thgir ti demit I fi oot snaf fo elpuoc a tuo ekat ylbaborP
…gniyas saw I ekiL“
.mih hcnual dluoc I
.tiucric lanoisseforp eht ni ’ninnur detah I
”.tnegru s’tI .klat ot deen eW
,sekatsim revird diova pleh ot smetsys ytefas cinortcele ehT
detnaw yllaer I lla nehW
.tleb sih rednu spal gnitteg ,seires rewol a ni owt ro raey a dneps ybboB dah—
”?ydaerla rood eht demmals uoy t’nevah yhw neht
,detiaw ylesoprup kciR
.siht tuoba klat dna edisni pets tsuj s’teL .saK ,esaelP“
.llub ’o enil taht em evig
,leehw eht gnippirg sdnah ym eciton neve t’ndid I
”.tog yllaer sgniht dab woh aedi ’nikaerf on evah uoy dnA
.thguoht I tahw s’tahT“
.niaga ti yas ll’I dna
.regnif eno htiw eybdoog evaw ot hguone gnol tsuj dnuora denrut ehs sa lla dna sselpot
.raey retfa raey spihsnoipmahc rof etepmoc ot desu ohw yug eht ekil ’nihton t’nia uoY
ytnewt rebmun no ni desolc I
.sleips yaD avoniaD esoht fo eno rehtona raeh ot deen t’nod I .ythgimla tsirhC“
,elzzum ym fo pil mottob eht tib I sa eromyna egrahc ni t’nsaw I ,yaw rehtiE
.siht dedeen I
.emit taes emos rof yadseuT yb kcart eht ta uoy evah nac ew
.me‘ kcip ot woh wonk erus I
pu seye ym gnivom erofeb sdnoces wef a gnikat ,desuap I
,gnitteg saw I derob woh wenk eH .ti
,raer tfel eht ni mih pilC
”.gniK ,knuf a tsuj naht erom saw tI“
toof gnihca ym htiw elttorht eht no nwod evirD
”.’nihton uoy ewo t’nod I“
”.ereh dnuora ’nitraf elddif pots annog m’I—kooL“
.RCSA eht htiw enod m’I .on s’rewsna ehT
.faed hcum ytterp deredisnoc eb d’I ,dnuos ot ytivitisnes neek ym rof neeb t’ndah ti fI
.owt nrut fo tuo gnimoc dnoces a fo shtnet lareves pu dekcip ylisae dna elttorht eht otni kcab depmuj I oS .mih detnaw yehT
.laiceps laer eb ot gniog saw ybboB
,hsinif t’ndluoc kciR
wenk kciR dna ,esac eht t’nsaw taht tuB       ”.detseretni…“
.riahc sih ni nwod kcab tas dna flesmih detcelloc kciR sa
”.aedi doog a eb annog saw taht thguoht ohw wonk ot evol d’I“
,esivorpmi t’ndluoc sgniht nmaD .stcnitsni on dah yehT
,suoicsnocbus ym otni deddebme tibah dab a ekil
,uoy dlot ydaerla I“
detartsurf dna gnisruc
stnednopserroc gniyonna eht dna
,kcab ’nimoc t’nia I
,em revo tpews regnuh ehT
”.selim 005 nur dna ereht ni pmuj nac enoyna tsuj toN
peed dna gnol gnilahxe
.hctertskcab eht ssorca erot ew sa
.did reven uoy dna
.reeb ym fo giws a gnikat erofeb dias I
,ton fi esuac ,yawa thgir rewsna ruoy wonk ot deen I dnA
.pu siht peek dluoc I regnol hcum woh rednow em edam tI
,edistuo demrots dna
syug eneg eht tuB
.taht neve ton ebyam ro
.daeherof sih no borht ot detrats lessev doolb a dna
”…ereht tuo teg I nehW
…semitemos tub ,sboj wolb paehc eht era rehtien llew ,haeY“
.gnitseretni dednuos reliart eht edisni morf gnimoc sesion eht teb I
detutitsni yeht ,stsoc tuc ot secar fo rebmun eht kcab gnilacs retfA
.ti rof emalb ot eno eht yletamitlu saw eh
,temleh eht no parts tsuj d’I
senil kcalb dilos eerht esoht fo espmilg a hctac d’I
ecar eht no sucof ot tluciffid saw ti erehw tniop eht ot gnir meht edam dna srae ym ta debbats enigne eht fo lworg gnicreip ehT
.ti gnillac era srotcod eht tahw s’taht ,tsael ta …rO
.ma I ekil trapa ’nillaf t’nia sremit dlo eht neve tuB
regnif yknip sih ni tnelat erom tog s’eh dnA“ .deilper kciR
.deracs dna toh ,dezzub rac siH
,saw I erehw ees ot kcab tfihs mih was I
,latem ekil yttirg dna prahs
.eettimmoc gnicaR raC kcotS otuA eritne eht dna ynneK rof loot ’nikcuf a eb oT
…tnedicni elohw tahT“
.yawa og niap eht ekam ot yaw eno ylno yllaer saw ereht
.rac eht htiw eussi na dnuof ylbaborP .syug werc tip eht fo eno saw ti ebyam rO .shpargotua yllis rof gniksa elpoep erom ,detnaw I tahw tsuj ,taerG
.htaerb ym dloh ot deirt I nehw s’tahT
”.rehtona ro yaw eno nI
.em emusnoc ot gnitrats saw sucof evitcurtsed no gniredrob dna evisolpxe siht ,ssendnilb sihT
”.stobor nmad eht emac neht dna
stops ralucric krad eht edisgnola thgir kcab ym nwod gninnur
.neve yrtnuoc elohw eht ,trops eritne eht dezigrene uoY
.tuo nap t’ndid hcihw serusaem fo sepyt lla
.emas eht od d’ehs gnipoh
,lla ti morf yawa
.edisni pu gniliob sgnileef lanrac esoht tuoba thguoht I sa
eht dna ,erohs eht tsniaga gnihsarc retaw fo evaw tnaig a ekil ydob ym gniflugne
.hcum taht neve ton ebyam ,secar erom wef