ro – taht fo erus ekam ot bonkrood eht revo trihs esool a gnah dna rood sih rednu lewot a ffuts dluohs eh ebyam tuB
– riah pu taps dna demrof selcillof sa
,sthgin sselpeels retfa
",denrecnoc tahwemos er'eW"
,snoituacerp ycerces dna ytefas rehto sih hguorht nar eH
– dum laudiser yna fo thgis eht gnidulcco
…sgniht taht dnatsrednu eW"
;sdoirep neves lla hguorht ekawa ylevitinifed mih tpek gniyrrow tnatsnoc eht ,dnah eno nO
.meht ot yas dluow eh tahw wonk t'ndid eH
,snoitseuq yna ,revo klat ot ekil d'uoy gnihtyna s'ereht fI
.fooh elgnis a htiw
.tlef eb dluoc moordeb sih fo erutarepmet eht ni noitaretla tneuqesnoc eht dna
?hguoht ,yerg riah rieht eyd reve dluow ohW
– tpael dna srevoc eht ffo werht ylkciuq eH
,lla retfa ,saw eH
,llabteksab tuoba t'nera taht seirots llabteksab ni detseretni er'uoy fI
.hguoht ,yarg ro thgiarts toN
denehtgnel sraE .talf
.detterf eh yadloohcs eht hguorht llA
,niloC dias ",wonk I"
eht-fo-tuo'  suoivbo-os-ho eht s'eh AF no dna ,esroH-
ev'ew ;ti tuoba demahsa eb t'ndluohs uoY .larutan s'tI
.roolf eht tsniaga yldednim-tnesba
.yxob gnitteg tsirw ,gnitniop sdne
eot eno htiw ti rednu teknalb a devohs eH .ti gnikcol dna
,no deggard sruoh ehT   …lleW
.sgnaf fo riap a deen d'eH
.od thgim ,seporhtnacyl llim-eht-fo-nur ,lamron meht fo lla
",drah s'ti wonk I
.yart a no puos eldoon nekcihc dna aet elimomahc dereviled rehtom sih elihw
.mih deppirg msaps rehtonA
.krow dluow siht depoh eH
,gninwaY .pu nehserf ot
,nedrah dna nekciht ot nageb slianregnif sih sa strohs dna
.edistuo morf ni gnimaerts won saw taht thgilnoom eht ni revo dnah sih denrut eH
odeloT yb "terceS"
.ti hguorht og ot dah lla
.etirovaf sih neeb syawla dah taht erutaretil flowerew fo ygolohtna eht ton saw koob ehT
.tser eht rof aracsam s'rehtom sih fo elttil a laets dluoc eh ebyaM .???$ :traM-laW fo noitces erac riaH
.hsiws rehtona ni wodniw eht nepo werht dna
eohs sinnet eno fo eot eht gnikcik
".elbareffusni s'ti hguoht nevE" .kniw A
.seye s'rehtaf sih teem ot pu dekool eh dna ,eb ot ti detcepxe dah niloC
.dnah eno htiw ti tsniaga riahc ksed sih dellup dna
elims kaew a evag niloC
sgnivas thgilyad fo tesno eht yb denetrohs saw thgilnus nmutua etal eht tub
deen d'eh setunim neetfif eht naht reilrae mih esuor ot gniyrt pu gnivig ylraen stnerap sih
sih fo ecnedive eht laecnoc ot elba saw eh fi nevE
"!yrtemonogirt ni ekawa yatS
.krowloohcs rof detaticapacni saw dna
.diovo emaceb slipuP
.detsiwt ti sa nrub ot nageb hcamots s'niloC
.ylruC .esraoC .etihW
.pu mih kcip ot rehtom sih rof llac dna
,eborhtab sih ni flesmih parw d'eh
.ega siht ta neppah
,ylimaf sih tahw wonk ot tnaw t'ndid eH
,esuoh eht dniheb sdoow eht drawot ffo gnireggatS .nwal eht otno
.loohcs ot og ot evah uoy won tuB"
.oiranecs retfa oiranecs hguorht derednaw dnim sih dna lamron naht snossel eht morf ssel neve denaelg eh
redluohs sih no dnah a fo psarg mrif A ".pleh
redluohs eno revo gabkoob sih gnignils ,tuo gnippoh noos saw eh dna
ehT-odeloT s'eh AD nO
noitop dehctob a dekooc yeht sa seoreh fo oirt eht depolevne dah loord fo loop erutainim a dna
,emoh gninruter nopU
ydob sih revo lla detpure gnihcti nA
".efas er'uoy erus ekam ot tnaw tsuj eW"
.ti gnikcol ot noitidda ni bonkrood eht tsniaga riahc a porp neve
.seirellag trAtnaiveD ro ytiniffAruF sih ni gnitirw sih fo erom dnif nac uoy
.llef noos ssenkrad dna )deggurhs eh
,revewoh ,rehto eht no
,thgin eno detnorfnoc eb ylbaborp dluow eh
.citsinalem ebyaM
,trohs saw loohcs ot evird ehT
– ylleb sih gnihctulc ,tib a gnikrej tuohtiw ton
.deb sih rednu ti erots dna tamrood artxe na reflip dluoc eh ebyam
?thgin eno mih no deips ylsuoititperrus yeht daH
naht gnirussaer erom saw
,wodniw sih edistuo egdel eht otno yldrawkwa flesmih detluav eH
.pleh ot ereh er'ew
skeew wef tsap eht revo sessalc lareves ni ffo gnizod neeb dah eH
?gniht doog a si sihT .kcehC
lleb eht fo gnignir lanif eht tsap deunitnoc sgnisum ehT
srevoc sih rednu ecnalg yna nekat dah yeht fi tub
dehsur elihw dluoc eh sa yltfos sa ni gnisolc ,rood eht ot
,etelpmoc erom eb dluow thginoT .won lluf saw tI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.thginot ereh tuo tnecs sih hctac dluow eno on taht yltnevref dehsiw eh
.tsurt nac uoy seno eht er'ew tub"
?gniod saw eh tahw wonk yeht diD
.gnihcterts teef sih leef dluoc eH   .dettaM
.detcepxe eh naht retsaf gnimoc saw tI
nworb sumuh fo skaerts nees evah dluow yeht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,yrtneer etatilicaf ot sa os ylthgils dettils wodniw eht evael ot dah syawla eH
,spmulc owt otni gnigrem erew sregnif siH .esnetni erom
,roolf dnoces eht no deb sih ot detaerter eH
.gnineffits erew teef dna sdnah siH
".yltnecer thgin ta esuoh eht fo tuo gnikaens neeb ev'uoy taht deciton evah I dna rehtom ruoy ,niloC"   odeloT yb
,)snoicipsus yalla suht dna yad yreve ylreporp deb sih gnikam yb siht diova ot deirt eh(
sralucirrucartxe sih piks ot dediced ,won hsirevef
,dah eh hcihw( ehcadaeh lufwa na depoleved dah eh taht stnerap sih decnivnoc eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
"terceS"   'skob-
draobyek tnaig a no yrots a tuo gniknulp fo tcepsorp eht evarb ot
,laerec sih otni noops eht debbad dnah thgir siH
.elbideni dna yggos erom dna erom emaceb srehto elihw tsiom sekalf lanoitidda gnitteg
si yrots s’yadot dna
?lavomer eht ti saw ro(
,snoitalupinamotohp seod ,sehcteks yliramirp ohw esroh a si ohw
.gniyps neeb dah yeht ekil mees t'ndid tI
.rehtom gnirac-reve sih morf kcep eybdoog kciuq a retfa ecnartne eht drawot gnidnuob dna
dna daorb gnimoceb hteet sih
)yllufecargnu etiuq(
,niloC dna ,doirep tsal fo dne eht delangis taht
.gnihtolc s'flowerew ni peehserew a
,pohs emutsoc ro ekoj :nwod toJ
.ecaf sih fo edis rehtie no ylpmil deppolf dna
.muelonil nehctik eht ni eucilruc ralucitrap a no ezag rieht xiffa ot nwod kcab meht detrad niloC erofeb dnoces tilps a rof tem seye rieht dna ,rehtom sih dias
.daetsni rettoP yrraH pu dekcip dah eH
,tnemom a rof evitcepsortni ,desuap rehtaf sih
?5$ ebyam
.rac eht ot tuo rehtom sih dewollof dna
,snoisrucxe ylthgin
)eno lacisyhp a ton tsuj
– ni emac eh nehw teef sih epiw ot luferac erom hcum eb dluohs eH
.emac ti ereh ,on hO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
nwod depmuj ereht morf dna
,ecaf sih morf yawa dellup eson siH
:deb sih ni gniyl ysword neeb evah tsum niloC
eet sih ffo dellup eH !noos ,kciuQ
hguone drah sekirts noitaripsni nehw setirw dna
.esnopser eht rof deraperpnu dna
koob doog htiw pu delruc eh erehw
.emitemos emoc dluow siht taht wenk eH
,odeloT yb "terceS" saw sihT
?esle enoyreve naht tnereffid s'eh tuo gnidnif enoemoS
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.htrof dna kcab kcik dluow teef sih erehw
?eyd riah emos ebyaM
.moorhtab s'eltryM gninaoM ni
.yad taht ylrae detalumrof dah eh esoht gnidulcni
enola dna desopxe
,ecaf sih rednu deyalps ,tuo daerps erew segap s'rettoP yrraH
.yllaer ruf ,saw ti kciht