.sgniht lla ni ees I ytuaeb eht s'tahT
...“ ".ecnahc a ti gnivig dnim t'ndluow I“
.flesym ,aedi eht revo yllautca m'I“
.sseug I ,flesym gnitah
.swap sih no daeh sih detser ecaredniC ,hgis a htiW
.ssenllits eht ni ytuaeb neddih a s'ereht
rehto hcae gnileef yleerf won sdnah rieht
.wap s'rehto eht fo dloh koot yltneg dna
.spil sih no regnif a detser eh sa
,taorht sih ni pmul eht
,sgnileef ruoy truh ot gniyrt t'nsaw I
,noeletnI ot resolc hcni na dils ecaredniC ".yadot
eht eb t'now I taht gniwonK
"?siht fo lla ta gnirats neeb tsuj ev'uoy oS“
tif gnihgual suoretsiob a otni denrut dna werg ylwols sihT
.ti htiw yako m'I dna
ecaredniC sa dnim sih dedoolf
,deilper erah eht ,elkcuhc a htiW ".poH
,aera eht dennacs eh sa
,redluohs sih no dnah a decalp noeletnI
.emit eht lla deirc tsuj ohw enoemos ot esol yltnatsnoc t'ndid uoY“ ".dab
,ecnedifnoc ruoy fo gnikniht tpek I
.ydaerla os yas ot tsaf smees ti timda od I“
.skcart sih ni mih gnippots
.daeh s'erah eht pota ssik a detnalp noeletnI
.ecaredniC revo gniyduts elihw flesmih ot demmuh drazil ehT ".emas
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
"?eb ti lliw tahw oS
.klat ot ecnahc siht dah ew dalg m'I dna
'?rehtob yhw os ,em ekil dluow eno on ,em htiw laed dluow eno oN'
.em ot eniuneg sleef reven ti tub
"?uoy gnippots s'taht lla yllaer s'tahT“
ytilanosrep ym tuoba tahW
,snoitidnoc esoht rednu worg ot ton drah eb dluow tI“
I“ .kcab spets wef a ekat ot ecaredniC gnisuac
.sraet sih yawa depiw ylkciuq
,mih revo delwarc drazil eht
noeletnI erofeb
",erofeb yrgna gnitteg
ylbirret esol d'I
"?tohS epinS desu I nehw llits doots uoy yhw taht sI“ ".flesym
.deunitnoc eh elihw epacsdnal eht sdrawot derutseg dna
.syug rehto etad tsuj t'nod syuG
.rediw ylthgils tog seye sih neht
,roolf eht sdrawot denrut ezag siH
metsys s'ecaredniC hguorht tohs tloj rehtonA
,teem ew emit txen ehT“
!sseltcat m'I fi sa tca uoY“
,dlob os syawla erew uoY
,rehto hcae ot gnissefnoc
,tnereffid sleef ylurt ti fI
,noitcetorp ,emoh a si tI
.em tuoba ti edam adnik I …I dnA
,esruoc fO“ "?huh ,did uoy …uoY“
,dehcnelc stsif siH
stessa elbaulavni fo arohtelp a gnitaerc
.regnad otni tsrifdaeh hsur dluow uoy
,ecaredniC otno nwod thgiew sih derewol yltneg noeletnI .drazil eht no dloh sih denethgit eh sa
"…aohW“ .tsen a ni sevodiP
.mih ot txen nwod gnittis
.detsisni ecaredniC "!yrros m'I-
,noeletnI sdrawot revo decnalg eh sa
sa nees era ronaemed dna noitcid yM
,'lairetam gnitad'
.noitnetta s'erah eht gnirenrag
",gnitiaw sreniart ruo peek ton s'teL“
elims ot tnemom a flesmih dewolla erah ehT
.hguorht delevart ecaredniC taht aera eht derevoc yrebburhs dna ,seert
,gniraelc a ni ,yllautnevE
,eson sih ta dekool ecaredniC
,noitisop taht ni deniamer
dnah a detnalp noeletnI
dna kcab sdaeh rieht gnillup
,tcapmi eht morf revo delkcub eH
.roolf eht ot dekool eh sa deremmis ecaredniC "…I …I-
.drow tsal eht dias eh sa eson eht no erah eht gnippat yltneg
.sreniart gnitiawa rieht sdrawot ,dnah ni dnah
H“ .kcab pets rehtona koot erah eht
.uoy morf taht raeh ot tcepxe t'ndiD“
deffuh ecaredniC " .yltneliS
,deilper erah eht
.efil ruoy evil ot woh uoy gnillet eb t'ndluohs I“ .nageb eh
,llih eht pota tas
",naem I tahw s'tahT“
.enoemos dnif tsael ta dluohs uoY !llits tub
I ,ynnuf t'nsi sihT !yeh-
",tnasaelp rehtar tlef taht ,timda I“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,segnellahc myg ehT
m'I taht decnivnoc ton llits m'I“
spil s'erah eht depacse naom feirb A
,trap eht yalp ylniatrec nac I
,ecnahc eht em evig neve t'now uoy tub
.flesmih ot detniop eh sa demialcxe erah eht "!deneppah siht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,erah eht dehcaorppa eh sa pu gnidnats
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,thguof ew emit yreve tub
tsuJ“ "?ti tuoba tahW“
"?leef dluow taht woh aedi yna evah uoy oD
"?nwod em wols t'ndluow gge na esuaceb dluohs I tuB“ ".nwod
,ecnamor dna em rof tfel esle hcum t'nsaw ereht taht deveileb I
,redluohs s'erah eht evoba
"!si ti tahw yltcaxe s'taht ,oN“ "-s'ti
,ecaredniC morf erats dexelprep a tub gnihton saw erehT ".plup
",enif s'ti ,on ,on-N“ "-
"…dnatsrednu uoy kniht t'nod I“
.noeletnI ot kcab neht
"?'gnihtyna egnahc ot gniyrt tniop oN' yas
,dlot eb hturT“
.erew uoy sa tnedifnoc sa eb ot detnaw I
deciton dna dnuora denrut eh sa deppots eh "-
esuap a saw erehT ".klat
,skcart sih ni deppots noeletnI ".woh em llet os
,desuap ecaredniC "…poH tub
.dehgis drazil ehT “ ...tsuj ,oN“
.sgel sih deppirg ylthgit eh sa gnilims
rehtegot sdaeherof rieht gnisserp
.ecaf sih no hsulb a htiw
,worbeye na desiar ecaredniC
,nosreP emoS yb ”tohS ruoY gnitoohS“ saw sihT
.nwod su wols tsuj dluow taht ,gge na edam dna pu dewercs ew fi tub
meht fo ynam erus m'I dna ,ereht tuo nomekop fo ytnelp s'erehT
.seenk sih dniheb noeletnI dekcik dna
.tniop siht yb gniklat enod ylekil era rotciV dna poH“ .pu doots eh
,deklaw nomekop htob
.elkcuhc a htiw deilper drazil eht
,yalpsid skrowerif a ekil tlef sedisni siH
.tnemom taht ta niht gnileef ria eht
,su dnuora dlrow eht ot
.rehtegot snalp ekam ll'ew
,rehto hcae ta derats nomekop htoB ".yrt
!teb I ,oot ,maet ym no dnA“ .delley eh
…adnik detrats I …tsuj I neht tuB
,tsehc eht ni mih ekirts ot demees tloj a ,ylnedduS
”tohS ruoY gnitoohS“   :yojne esaelP
nomekop htoB .ssik a rof
,ssik ot deunitnoc yeht sa
",nialpxe ot em wolla ,ysae ,ysaE“
,ytilaer ot kcab flesmih deppans erah ehT
pets hcae htiw drawrof gniklaw
pu doots noeletnI .secaf rieht fo htob no elims llams a
,niaga si ti erehT“ ".tuo
was I nehw dekcilc
.daeh s'ecaredniC htiw level eb ot dnah thgir sih desiar eH
.sseltniop saw ti ekil tleF
citamsirahc sa ecaredniC A
,kcab ecnedifnoc ym gnitteg detrats I
,uoy dnuora dlrow eht evresbo dna tis ylurt ot emit gnikat yB
,melborp xamanyd eht
"?neht dna...“ ".ti ta kool
hsulb ot detrats eh "…uoy
.redneg fo esuaceb ylno s'ti smees
.thgir rieht ot eert a ot gnitniop ,nageb eh
.htaerb peed a ni werd dna
"?uoy evol I taht yas ot tsaf oot ti si …sI“
ecaf dehcnurcs enO
.mra s'drazil eht ot dnahkcab thgil a htiw deilper eh
.gniog peek ot detavitom erew llits uoy
detseretni ton er'uoy ebyam ,rehto hcae gnivol pots ew ebyam
.rehto hcae morf yawa htdaerb s'riah a spil rieht gnicalp dna
rehto hcae ta derats htob yehT
.hteet sih dettirg erah ehT
,egatnavdasid ruoy etipseD
.mih sdrawot denrut noeletnI ".erew
.poH esaelp ot dna elttab ot nomekop dnif ot etatiseh t'ndluow uoY
,syad regnuoy ruo nI“
,erah eht ot resolc tog eH ".si
.roolf eht ta erats ot deunitnoc eh sa depoord srae s'ecaredniC ".os sseug I …haeY“
,deworruf worb sih
.yenruoj ruo nageb tsrif ew ecnis reve
"?ti si ,sdnuos ti sa ysae sa toN“
.guh a rof ni ecaredniC dellup eh ,noitatiseh tuohtiW " ...revewoH
?yawa meht dnes dna gurhs annog tsuj uoy erA
pirg sih denethgit erah ehT
.dehcaorppa ylwols drazil ehT ".etarobale
a ot mih taeb dluow I dna rotciV eetnaraug nac I
"?su neewteb tuo krow t'nseod ti fi nevE“ ".gnihtyna
.ton ro ti egdelwonkca ew rehtehw
,ezag sih gnitreva deunitnoc eH ".ti s'taht …hu tsuJ
.em rof krow t'nseod citnamor a eb ot gniyrt tub ,taht ylno toN
.nwod srehto gard tsuj dluow I taht
"?snoisiced ym ni detsevni os gnitteg uoy era yhW“
,yawa dellup eh ,yllautnevE
dnif nac uoy dna
,daeh sih fo ekahs a htiW
gnidn eirfeb neve
.rehtegot swap sih gnibbur ylthgils elihw desuap eH ".toobaR
.sdnah sih ta kool ot desuap eH ".srehto
knurt eht ta nwod gnittis
.niaga syug uoy delttab ew nehw flesym no nwod llits saw I“
,retsaf werg gnihtaerb sih
.og ot syaw a dah llits I woh dna
,gniylper erofeb yawa decnalg ylfeirb noeletnI
.kcab s'noeletnI gnola swap sih deggard yltneg
ylluftsiw dehgis eH ".og
,deilper drazil eht ,ffocs a htiW
!htiw eb ot tnaw I taht
,seY“ "!?gnol tahT“ ".yenruoj
,wap sih ta dekool ecaredniC
.sgnidnuorrus ym ot erom dna erom gniciton nigeb I neht
,gnorw em teg t'noD“
.redluohs s'ecaredniC dettap ylthgil noeletnI ".ylbatibudnI“ "?huh ,tol a neeb sah …tI“ "...atnezamaZ
.elims mraw a htiw tem saw kool sih tub
.sgel sih dnuora smra sih gnipparw
,hcram yltnelis ot deunitnoc drazil ehT
sa ti nees ylno evah d'uoy
esuac' ,semoctuo eseht fo yna htiw yako eb dluow I !trats eht morf
htaerb s'noeletnI fo gnileef eht gnirovas
!dam em sekam tahw s'taht dna
.ti yb snoitnetni lli on evah I tub
.erom hcum os si eert siht taht ees nac uoy
"?em wohs uoy t'nod yhW“
.erah eht  fo tnorf ni yltcerid gnieb won
,tuo dellac eh ",tiaW“
?yltnecer adnik …sseug I“
,sselpleh dna kaew os tlef syawla I“
.noitcerid emas eht morf gnimoc ,dedda rotciV
dessap stnemom lareveS
,dias dna psag a htiw yawa dellup erah eht nehT .seye ediw htiw
ni mih dellup dna
,seye s'noeletnI morf gniruop nageb sraet ,ylnedduS
,tsrif ta deracs em edam llits tI '.syug ekil I'
.siri sih ni enil yreve gniyduts fi sa seye sih otni gnirats
.yks eht ta gnirats ,desuap eh
,tnemom rehtona gnitsaw tuohtiW "-tsuj I
,esle enoyna tuoba taht ekil teg t'ndluow I
ecnalg evitisiuqni na htiw kcab gnirats noeletnI ees ot pu gnikool
.derumrum ecaredniC ",uoy evol I“
,ssarG  nosreP emoS yb
.srehto ot ytiroirepus fo ria na
nihc s'ecaredniC gnippuc yltneg
,deliocer noeletnI .seye sih morf gniliart sraet fo maerts llams a dna
"?maet ruoy no slrig eht fo yna htiw pu gnikooh deirt uoy evah“
retpahc txen eht trats ot ydaer
.tegrat sih dnuof eh
.deddon erah eht ,elims a htiW ".flesruoy
.gnillor deunitnoc sraet eht sa
.ti ta gnikool peek dna
,flesruoy deirrac uoy woh dna
,pu gnivig ton
.sehcnarb gniltsur yb dewollof
,tniop ruoy redisnoc nac ew neht
W“ .depoord ylthgils
;mih ta kcab gnirats ecaredniC
"?siht htiw yako yllaer er'uoy …oS“
.ti deiduts dna ssarg fo edalb elgnis a dekculp noeletnI ,yltneliS
.seye sih ta depiw dna hgual ot
.erusaelp lautum rieht revo psag dna ,sserac
tsuj gnihtemos dna
.troffe tnailav a ti evag uoy
elttab eht retfa tub
,remraw werg ecaf sih sA ".em ssiK“
dna revo llor
.nwO ruO fO evihcrA dna yrruFoS no
.lrig a erew uoy fi uoy etad d'I .esruoc fo ,lrig a erew uoy fi ,naem I“
.swap sih ni ecaf s'drazil eht fo dloh gnikat
.dnah tfel sih no daeh sih detser eh sa
.namow a m'I dneterp ,tcaf nI
.deilper yletaidemmi eh ",oN“
flesruoy llet annaw tsuj uoY ?uoy tuB
…daer ot ikahK rof ysae s’ti os stnedni on htiw lairA stp61 si siht dna ,thgin ymrots dna krad a saw tI   .yenruoj rieht fo
.thgir sih ot nwod tas ecaredniC ".yrenecs eht yojne d'I derugif I
,tuo krow t'ndluow ti ebyaM
,feirb saw ti emit siht ,revewoH
traeh sih ot wap a tup eH
,suoicilam ylurt gnihtyna naem t'ndid uoY“
.dab taht t'nsaw ti ,won emoc ,hO“
noisserpxe eht denruter eH
.srae sih fo eno htiw gniyalp elihw
.drazil eht revo gnirewot
srae s'ecaredniC
,yrartnoc eht nO“ ".ereh
.daeh sih detfil erah eht
.emas eht sleef tsuj lla tI“
"!og attog ew ,noeletnI“
.dnah sih gnivaw dna kcab gninrut erofeb
.kcab gnillup ylwols nehT .knilb A
,roolf eht no elihw
,tniop emos ta esoppus I“
yas ot flesym yb emit emos dnif d'I gninrom yreve os
eert eht tsniaga kcab denael eH
denaorg ecaredniC
"?huh ,taht od dluow I ,haeY“
,elbmert ot detrats ecaredniC
.redluohs s'erah eht no dnah a gnicalp erofeb pu doots dna dehgis noeletnI ,ylnedduS
S“ .etar-traeh gnisaercni sih erongi ot gnilggurts
,deppots ylneddus noeletnI
,tsrif ta ti fo kniht ot tahw wonk t'ndid I .em tih
,eert eht ta kooL“
"!yad emos taht rof kcab uoy teg ot deen llits I dna …seY“
sdnah s'noeletnI fo htob tlef eH
.em ssik neht ,ysae os s'ti fI
,dneirf sih drawot dekool eH
"?uoy era erehW !ecaredniC“
,eert eht sdrawot deklaw dna
.tcatnoc otni gnimoc ylraen sedis rieht
",llew os wonk I ecnagorra eht s'erehT“
ton er'uoy kniht llits uoy od...oS“
,sknab yromem rieht otni hcuot s'rehto hcae fo gnileef eht dehcte yehT
.noitcerid rehto eht ni koot erah eht
.srehto pleh ot gnilliw os ,tnedifnoc os
.tfel ew nehw uoy ssim dluow I dnA .reippah tol A
.snialp eht ta tuo dekool eh sa
uoy erussa I neht
,gniremmihs seye siH .ruf sih gnittih
"?rof taht saw tahW
.uoy rof emas eht seog tI“
uoy oD“ .detuohs eh
.erus m'I ,uoy did sA
,yrt a ti evig ot gnitnaw
,erac t'now srehto eht wonk I …I“
.flesruoy fo ylwol os kniht ot ton yrt os
.sregnif sih ni edalb eht lriwt ot detrats noeletnI
,detloj ylneddus nomekop htoB
.thgiarts pu tas neht eH
.esiwrehto em ecnivnoc ot ytinutroppo na si siht dna ,ereh thgir m'I
.tcatnoc gnikam nopu sih dleh hcihw
.erutnevda eht etiuq dah ev'ew neht ecnis dnA“
.hgis a htiw deilper eh
.redrah dna redrah gnikrow tpek I tub
"!uoy ekil dluow eno on emussa ot gniog tsuj er'uoy tub
.yadot era ew ereh neht dnA
,drawrof deppets ecaredniC
,erom ecno ssik ot drawrof dehsup erah ehT
.ecneirepxe gninethgirf tsom eht saw flaheb s'rotciV no thgif ot gniyrT
,selttab fo gnirts gnidne-reven eht
!eguh emaceb htob uoY
ezag s'ecaredniC ffo detcelfer tesnus ehT
.erom ecno gnissik erofeb htaerb a ni ward ot stnemom feirb gnikat
,emit emos etiuq rof uoy rof gnihtemos tlef ev'I
"'?fi tahw' gnirednow kcuts eb t'now I tsael tA“
.flesym denoitseuq I nehw tlef I woh ekil saw tI .doog yllaer
,rehto hcae ta derats nomekop htoB "!elohssa diputs uoy
"…ti tuoba gnikniht tsuj deracs teg I
!sgnileef rieht redisnoc d'I esruoc fO
.noitisop taht llif ot gnilliw sdneirf dna
.dnah s'noeletnI sdrawot neht
”!revo lla uoy rof gnikool neeb ,yeH“
tnemom taht ta saw tI
,gniht eno s'taht nomekop ekil t'ndid uoy fI
,tnereffidni neve ro ,hsiffodnats dnuos yam I semitemoS
neht dna ,drah dekrow I
,gnitroter erofeb tnemom a rof derats erah ehT ".ti
,tif gniyrc a ni nwod kaerb d'I ro ,retnec nomekop a ni pu ekaw dna
deppots drazil ehT ".sruoy
.eert A ;taht tsuj
.taht fo thgis esol t'nod uoy erus ekaM
dna ,tuo gnimoc tpek tsuj sdrow ehT“
.roolf eht otno ylsuoinomerecnu gnillaf
.yawa gniklaw nageb eh sa detats eh
nekciuq ot detrats gnihtaerb siH
”tohS ruoY gnitoohS“
pil rewol sih fo edisni eht gnitib
.s'noeletnI yb detcepsni gnieb eugnot sih tlef eh sa
.dnuora gnicap detrats dna
”?ot teg eh did erehW“ ,flesmih gniksa
.elims eltneg a htiw kcab dekool neht
syob etuc tuoba seirots etirw ot detnaw eh dediced dna yad eno pu ekow tsuj ohw ,nosreP emoS yb
.kcab sih no dial eh sa dedaf elims siH ".erus
.erofeb syug gnikil tuoba thguoht reven I
,tnereffid s'ti taht niatrec os er'uoY“ "!?tahW“
dneirf sih ta kcab gnirats noeletnI
.erah eht nihtiw pu denepo tip a fi sa tlef ti ,tnemom taht tA .ssenitpmE ".yaw
.yawa gniklaw nageb eh sa dedda eh
.sruoy eb ot gniyd eb dluow
,dnah a tuo dehcaer eh
.regnuoy erew ew ecnis nworg evah ylurt uoY“ ,deilper noeletnI
detrats eh litnu pu
.ssucsid ot srettam emos evah ew kniht I“
seirots sih fo erom
.yaw siht ti referp I ,revewoH
.seye sih ni kool luftsiw a htiw ssenredliw nairalaG eht ta tuo gnirats
.lwocs ot ecaredniC gnisuac
,niaga yawa denrut eh ,deppots eh ecnO ".uoy
.thgir sih ot ssarg eht gnittap dna
,gnisrevnoc ysub era rotciV dna poH sa gnol sA“
.nirg yls a htiw deksa noeletnI
.serutseg citnamor ot evisnopser yletelpmoc eb ll'I taht eetnaraug on s'erehT“ .nageb eh
.su fo owt eht tsuJ
,erutaerc esrevid a si erutaN .ecnanetsus
tnemom a rof yltnelis doots nomekop owt ehT ".od
.neht ,dnim ruoy attuo derob eb tsuM“ ".deednI“
",enoemos dnif nac uoy erus m'I .dalg m'I...“
.swap sih ta gnikool
,flesym gnitah yb erehwyna teg ot gniog t'nsaw I taht dezilaer I“
ot hsiw llits uoy od …revol tcefrep
.yawa dekool llits ecaredniC sa
"?wonk maet ruoy no esle enoyna seoD“
!?tahw-hW“ .thgirpu gnitloj erofeb semit wef a gniknilb yks eht ta derats drazil ehT
kcab gnirats erofeb rediw
.elkcuhc ot detrats eh nehw saw tahT
,worb desiar a htiw derats ecaredniC
.namow a dna nam a gnissik neewteb ecnereffid eht dnatsrednu em ekam si
.revoc sih morf tuo dekeep ecaredniC ".troffe
"?emit siht ,ssik tsenoh na ti ekam ew llahS“
"?nam rehtona dessik uoy evaH“ ".tnereffid
?uoy pots ot si ereht lla elam gnieb sI“
,don a dna elims a htiW
gniworg detrats seye sih erofeb detniuqs eh nehT
.pu dellab dah stsif sih dna
.sedisni sih gnihcrocs erew ti ekil tlef tuo dna ni htaerb yreve sa
,ekil …doog tlef I“
deunitnoc noeletnI
.teef sih ot tog eh ,ylwolS ".su
.noitcerid sih ni gniddon ,nageb noeletnI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.elkcuhc a htiw nageb drazil eht
…tsuj s'tI“ "?taht si yhW
.noitnetta s'erah eht gninrae ,deilper eh
.s'ecaredniC tem ezag sih os daeh sih derewol neht
,yawa spets wef a koot dna dnuora denrut eH
pu deklaw ecaredniC taht
,detaeper eh ", ecnahc a ti evig ll'I dias I“
semit erew ereht
"…esac taht nI“ .delims noeletnI
.tsrif ta enif demees ti dna ,wonk I slrig rehto htiw gnitteg deirt dna dekcinap I
.sesnes rieht fo dloh koot yeht litnu
,eert eht tsniaga dekcab won saw ecaredniC "…ton fi tub
,tniop riaF“ .ezorf noeletnI ".emit
,syug er'eW .nam ,no emoc ,yeh-H“ "?skool ym ro
",t'nevah I .on …I“
eh sa delffins drazil eht
.si ti woh wonk uoY
.erom ecno mih ssik ot drawpu denael eh sa hgual dna
.reisae gnitteg detrats ti tub
dewollaws ylyrd eH
.noitcerid s'noeletnI ni gniklaw ylwols dna pu gnidnats erofeb dehgis erah ehT
.tisiv ot secalp attol a tog ev'ew ,llew-
!won em ot netsil uoY
,noeletnI na emoceb d'uoY
s'tI“ "?pu evig ot gniog tsuj er'uoy oS“
.od yeht semitemos tub ,on yllamron toN“ ".syug
,leurc os erew eh fi dnA
.erutuf eht ni liomrut yrassecennu yna diova pleh dluow ti taht leef llits I dna
.spil s'ecaredniC sdrawot eugnot sih gnihsup yltneg
egnaro fo edahs a gninrut nageb yks ehT
.evol ot tnaw ew ohw gnivol dna
,erac dna noisicerp htiW
"!laed gib a fo dnik ma I sseug I ,haeY“
.meht dnuora  arua gnitacoffus a gnivael
!yawa em hsup ,ton fI
.mih revo gnirewot ylraen
,traeh sih ni noitatiseh eht yawa gniwotS
ylthgils a htiw dnuora gninrut
.kcab pets a koot eh dna ediw tnew seye sih sa
,maet ym no srekool laer emos era erehT
.esolc rehto hcae gnidloh dna
"!uoy etad dluow I ,kceH
.eye eht ni drazil eht gnikool ,deksa eh
.dnim sih dessorc thguoht tnerehoc on sa
,rehto hcae ta derats nomekop htob sa
,tnemom eht ni flesym esremmi I fI
.nrecnoc ruoy etaicerppa od I
!uoy ot siht nialpxe ot evah neve t'ndluohs I“
?rof gnitiaw uoy era tahW“
,,taht fo kniht t'ndid ,yakO“
.ezag sih deworran
"?seY“ "?noeletnI …yeH“
,sprihc fo yrrulf a
.yrt ot ton nosaer on evah uoy esoppus I nehT“
seye sih desolc eH ".seY“
.noitnetta s’drazil eht detcartta eh sa deralced eh
",kcab daeh dna noissucsid siht tegrof tsuj s'teL
.enoyna ot klat annaw t'ndid I
noeletnI dna ecaredniC
.noitceffa ot ralimis gnihtemos otni denrut uoy rof noitarimda ym
.em esaeler ot mih tnaw t'nod I“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tuo krow t'ndluow tsuj ti
.ecaf sih no gniworg elims a
…t'ndid I !yrros os m'I-I“
.aera eht ot gnirutseg elihw deksa eh
,ecaredniC sdrawot denrut dna desuap eh "…revewoH
.syad esoht ecnis ,ot dah I“
.ecaf rieht no skool teewsrettib htiw htoB
,ereht tuo nomekop fo dlrow elohw a s'erehT“
.etarobale nac uoy spahreP
.mih nihtiw mossolb htmraw gnileef
,sevael eht ni gniraelc llams a hguorhT
.ecaf sih ssorca daerps ot gnitrats hsulb a
.ecnamor rof tif ton m'I taht oga gnol detpecca I“ "?tahw uoY“
tsuj aedi eht neht dna
!uoy ni detseretni eb d'ohw nomekop s'ereht gnihtyna uoy teb I“
.dnah s'nomekop rehto eht rof tuo dehcaer eh
,pu kcab tas eh "…tub ,gnihtyreve
,don a dna elims a retfA
"?esnes yna ekam taht seoD
enoemos dnif dluohs uoY“
.revo mih gnikool elihw kcen sih gninarc
",em dnim t'nod ,hA“
,smees eh reniart eht si poH fI“
roolf eht no gniyl yllautneve
,taht htiw pu tup ot gnilliw enoyna ees t'nod I
.deddon dna seye sih desolc noeletnI ".gnuoy
"?emit txen litnu dloh no siht tup ll'ew esoppus I“
,ssik ot deunitnoc yehT
.mih ta pu gnirats erah gnihsulb
,drawrof daeh sih dellup yltneg noeletnI sa
.gnuoy erew ew ecnis tol a nworg yllaer ev'uoy ,wonk uoY“
.srae sih htiw flesmih derevoc ylwols
.elttil erew ew nehw morf tnereffid repuS
.ecaf s'ecaredniC no werg ylwols elims A ".sgniht
. deirt tsael ta ev'dluow ew
eht revo gnikool
"!ti gnitteg t'nera uoY“ ".efil
,ecitcarp hguorht em gnittup neeb s'poH
.si ti tnereffid woh em wohS“ "?tahw uoy wohs-
,ylbatrofmoc sevil citnamor ruo evil ot elba eb htob ll'eW
.llew sa gnihgual flesmih dnuof noos tub
,sboj ot em gnidnes
tuoba yrroS“ .gnidaf ylwols elims sih
,srae sih fo krep a htiW ".yleritne toN“
.em revo emac tahw wonk t'nod I“
",tsrif gnihtemos uoy ksa tsum I“
,dehcaorppa dna teef sih ot tog erah ehT ".ssucsid
noeletnI denioj ecaredniC
uoy sa suoretsiob dna
.gnihtyna naht erom ,seY“
!ecnahc a flesruoy gnivig neve ton er'uoy esuaceB“
draeh eh ylneddus nehw
snaf evah ot erus si
,pu doots dna ffuh a htiw detuohs eh
,uoy derujni ylsuoires dah I thguoht I
!ereh emirp ruo ni er'eW !nam ,no emoC ?oN“
"?evah uoy emussa I nehT“
.ezag sih deworran noeletnI
.syug htob er'eW .haey …lleW“
.thguoht ni yks eht ta gnirats saw ohw
.dnuorg eht otno derewol yltneg saw eh sa sredluohs sih pirg
,ecarbme eht denruter erah eht
,dneirf sih ta nwod dekool eH ".em
.revo tsim ot detrats seye sih sa
,evil ot tnaw ew woh gnivil
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,emit tsrif eht now I dna thguof ew nehW
I“ .ezag denediw
,deilper erah eht ,retal gurhs wols a dna
,sgniht reicips neve gnoma
daerps ecaf sih no hsulb eht dna
"…em tuoba kniht I nehT
.seye sih gniyrd osla saw ohw
! pu tuhs ,pu tuhs ,pu tuhs ,pu tuhS“
.rehto hcae ta dekool
.dnuora erew uoy nehw reippah tog I taht gnizilaer saw I“
ot gniog tsuj er'uoy dna
.tcaf ni ,uoy ekil tsuj eb ot detnaw I“
,tnemom a rof yawa dekool erah ehT
eh sa noitisop taht ni gniyats
.eert eht ta derats dna
"?thgir ,serac ohw os ,yad a ti llac annaw tsuj uoy tuB
.keehc sih bur yltneg ot revo
",eert taht ta kooL“
.kcab tohs noeletnI "!taht od t'ndluow I“
,nihc sih ot regnif a tup eH ".sgnidnuorrus
,esirprus htiw mih ta dekool noeletnI
skcatta elbbub dna snug retaw fo seiromeM ".thgif
.gnihcaorppa erofeb skeehc sih dettap yltneg eh sa flesmih dednimer eh ,won toN
.tuoba yrrow ot gnihton ev'uoy taht
,daeh sih yb drazil eht debbarg
,eralg a htiw revo gnikool ylwols ,deppots ecaredniC
dedda eh ",gnola emoC“
.yrasrevda tluciffid ylgnisaercni na emaceb uoy
.tnemesuma s'ecaredniC ot hcum ,dettimda eh
.oot ,hguorht tnew mooballiR segnahc eht dna ,hguorht tnew uoy segnahc eht tuoba kniht I .wonk t'nod I“
noeletnI ,dneirf siH
,dnah eerf s'drazil eht rof dnuora tlef wap drawyaw A
.tnemitnes eht emoclew I“
.elims gnitrofmoc a htiw detats noeletnI ",yllaer ,enif s'tI“ ".em
.niaga srae sih htiw gniyalp nageb erah ehT ".tcaf
.t'nod I diarfa m'I“ ".si
,delkcuhc erah ehT ".taht
dnah a dehcaer eh sa
"!toh s'nori eht elihw ekirts attoG
,lwarc a ot wols ot demees emiT
.tniop taht yb sretnuocne citnamor elbirret ynam-oot-eno fo dne gniviecer eht no saw I ,revewoH
,uoy snrecnoc siht woh ees ot liaf I“
,sevael eht hguorht gnivom tnazefnU na ees dluoc eh
uoy s'ti dna ,oga emit gnol a dnim ym pu edam I !meht tuoba erac t'nod I tub ,em etad annaw dluow taht ereht tuo nomekop fo tol a era ereht ebyaM
.kcab uoy evol lliw ohw
,yawa deklaw dna delims drazil eht sA
"?yaw siht tlef uoy evah gnol woH“
.thgif su evah dluow reniart ruoy neht dnA“
,eert siht yb nar uoy fI“ .nageb noeletnI
,nageb eh sa dnoyeb snialp eht ta dekool dna
"!serusaelp tseggib
.em tuoba yrrow ot deen t'nod uoy oS
.pots ot noinapmoc sih gnisuac
.toobaR a llits saw I nehw detrats yllaer tI
.elims a htiw pu kcab dekool neht
.ssik a rof rehtegot spil s'nomekop htob gnikcol
,yawa gninrut erofeb kcab gnirats
fo puorg a ot seirreb suoirav gnignirb
.meht dnuora erutan eht gnivresbo yltnelis ni
.eciov s'poH fo ecruos eht sdrawot seert fo puorg a dnoyeb gnikool
,deilper yltfos dna ecno deddon eh
.nageb drazil eht
,htaerb kciuq a gniward retfa nageb eh ",oS“
,era uoy ohw rof uoy gnikil ydaerla ,em s'ereH
.ecaf sih morf gniniard doolb eht leef dluoc eh sa wap sih gnihcnelc ylthgil
,ffo deid ezeerb eht
"!noitasrevnoc siht gnivah neve er'ew suolucidir s'tI
"?ecnamor rof tuo tuc
,nethgit taorht sih gnileeF ".tnemitnes
od ot evah uoy llA“
.hcum taht nworg ev'I fi llet t'nac I …tsuj I“
",evah ew sa hcum sa tsuj degnahc ev'uoy tub ,ti eciton ton thgim uoY“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
"…I …naem uoy …tub …hW“
s'efil fo eno gnicneirepxe tuohtiw og ot enim fo dneirf doog a tnaw t'nod I
.derevaw ronaemed citsaisuhtne sih sa derats ecaredniC ".flesym
.yllaer ,noitarimda fo esnes a saw ti tub
.sgnileef ym eralced ot egaruoc eht t'ndah llits I dna
noeletnI morf emac hgis A
,ynohpocac rieht deunitnoc nomekop htoB
.efil ym evil dluohs I woh em lleT .eunitnoc , esaelp tub
.hcuot eht morf delbmert spil sih dna
...atnezamaZ dna naicaZ
"?yrt tsenoh na siht evig
,yawa ekorb yltneg noeletnI
",ynnuf eb ot desoppus ton s'tI“ "-
.ereh tuo ta kool ot hcum toN
,deddil-flah gniworg seye sih
?uoy ekil yeht yas seod enoemos fi nalp ruoy s'tahW“
"!uoy etad annaw d'ohw maet ruoy no nomekop s'erehT“
,thgirb nrub ecaf sih leef dluoc erah ehT .derepsihw eh
.ecaf sih no elims eht ot yrartnoc