,kcuuuuuF“ .ereht ni flesmih dleh eh sa kcorB ot esolc gniyats ,tuo denaom trA ”…tihs ,wA“
.laeppa s’noinapmoc sih yned ot tluciffid ti dnuof eh taht hcus
”,risseY“ ”?won thgir ytpmE“
.dias eh ”,yrros ,thgir hO“
.pets s’naiva eht ni gnirps egnarts niatrec a saw ereht taht deciton mailliW
,kcab dellup neht eH
,teef sih detsujda neht eH
.sllats eht ot dekool eh erofeb ,ylsuoicsnocbus pu srehtaef liat sih tfil ylno dluoc torrap eht ,siht ot
”!ereh ni ycilop xes-on a tog ev’yehT“ .dias eh ”!won yeh-
,siht htiw dnA ”.ris ,seY“
”.yadot dnuora enim fo dneirf a gniwohs tsuJ“
”…edisni muc …hA …muC“ .dias eh
.yaw eht fo tser eht detfil srehtaef s’torrap eht taht egdir eye desiar a htiw gniton
.dehs gnieb gnihtolc fo dnuos eht yb derewsna saw trA ”?tsrif uoY“
.ecnartne s’torrap eht edisni eugnot sih gnisserp
raef ni ediw seye sih
”?thgir ,syob doog eb ll’uoy ,esruoc fO
.dias eh ”,yllaer toN“
,naicisum dna retirw a si ohw
.redluohs eht no trA gnittap
,emit dnoces a tuo dellup neht nogard elprup ehT
,sgniw sih fo srehtaef eulb thgil eht detnemelpmoc dnabtsiaw eht fo roloc eht
.no raewrednu on dah kcorB taht dezilaer eh taht neht ylno
”,ti teg od I ,ylsuoires tuB“
,trA dniheb dehcrep neht eH
.sremotsuc reihtlif rieht fo eno spahrep saw eh taht sromur fo ytnelp draeh dah eh tub
.dnoces a neve etatiseh ton did torrap ehT
.edis eht ot daeh sih detlit trA
.ylleb sih debbur eh sa redluohs s’torrap eht revo tahwemos depard daeh sih
.mih ta nwod dennirg eh yaw eht was torrap eht snoisserpxe laicaf s’kcorB dehctaw eh sa dna
.deddon kcorB .deksa eh ”?ecalP“
”,eituc ,no partskcoj nwo ruoy teg dluohs uoY“
”.rehguor elttil a og ot emiT“ .dias eh
,moor gnignahc eht fo llaw eht tsniaga sdnah sih decarb torrap ehT ”…haey hO“
,pu nethgit stnap sih tlef trA
.gnol erofeb taht fo pu-kcip a eb dluow ereht
”…ereh thgir ton-
,ecap eht deunitnoc eH
”,eituc ,em rof kcab dloh t’noD“
,kcoc drah taht gnirevoc cirbaf kcalb ehT
.ydob sih tsniaga partskcoj eht fo dnabtsiaw eht deppans kcorB ,siht htiW
.hcterts latnemirepxe na ti gnivig
.daeh sih gnikahs erofeb ,siht ta egdir eye na esor trA
,reganam rieht yb tuo dewehc neeb tsuj dah ohw enoemos rof yppah oot elttil a spahrep demees tI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,kcezzoW rreH yb
,revewoh ,did eh sA
,partskcoj eht fo parts eht tsap dekool neht eH
,nwod deliart sdnah s’kcorB
,denaorg eh os dna
ecalp ni selur wen lareves tup ot dah eh taht mih ekil sremotsuc fo esuaceb saw ti dna
.erots ni dah nogard eht tahw enigami ylno dluoc eh dna
.nib eht otni ti worht ,yssem steg gnihtyna fi
”?srehtaef ym sehctam siht yas uoy dluow hcum woH“
partskcoj eht gnivohs dna drawrof gnihcaer
,ylirgnuh pu ti deppal eH .ecnartne taht tsniaga redrah dna redrah gnisserp eugnot sih
.rennacs eht ot kcab gnikool erofeb ,fo tuo emoc dah yeht moor gnignahc eht ot gnikool ,desuap eH
H“ .tsehc eht no kcorB gnippals yltneg erofeb delkcuhc tub ,dehsulb trA
,dor nwo sih ot emac sdnah sih fo eno ,yldI
,yad eht ni ylrae rehtar saw ti
.ylgnicitne ecnartne s’trA tsniaga dehsurb eugnot sih neht dna ,ni denael kcorB
,dees fo stnuoma suoipoc htiw sedisni sih doolf nogard eht tlef trA
,drah emac eh sa kwauqs duol a tuo tel torrap eht ,neht dnA
.moor eht ni hcneb eht revo mih gnidneb
:won yb llird eht wonk uoY“
.kcab gniklaw ,denrut worc eht
.deksa eh ”?tahw esaelP“
.pu ti dellup ylwols kcorB sa gnihctaw erofeb
:partskcoj eht dracsid ot ytinutroppo eht gnikat ,kcab sih no tas eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.nihtiw peed flesmih gnidloh
.ereht kcab evissergga-evissap repus dednuos eH“ .dias eh
.moor gnignahc eht otni mih del kcorB erofeb
,siht ta kaeb sih denepo trA
,edisni htgnel eht fo eniltuo eht
:rorrim eht tsap ylthgils detoocs osla eH
:netfo os yreve ssa sih ta decnalg kcorB yaw eht thguac osla trA ,revewoH
.delims eh ,rorrim eht ni flesmih ta dekool eh sa dna
,eugnot sih deppop eh ,esnopser nI
”!uoy llet em tel ,siht fo eceip a teg ot evol dluow noitanicsaF ta syug eht teb I
”.ereh dnuora hcum torrap a ees I kniht t’noD“
”.hctam seod tI“
!ereht fo tuo teg dna spartskcoj yrt ot ,spot ,setunim net evah yeht ,no won morF“
”…mM“ .retsaf tib elttil a tsuj
.dehsulb eH ”…naem I“
.dias eh ”,kcorB ,thgir erew uoy ,haeY“
.stsurht eht tsniaga kcab gnihsup mih leef ot detrats kcorB gnol erofeb dna
.skeehcssa s’torrap eht neewteb ni ti dnirg ot nageb dna
daeh s’kcorB dniheb pu gnimoc dnah eno
,kaeb sih fo tnorf ni deniamer partskcoj ehT
,esirprus ni pu pmuj torrap eht ekam ot hguone saw eporg ehT
!timmaddog ,partskcoj a tuo yrt ot setunim neetfif ekat ton seod tI
.thgil eht ni gnitnilg shtworg kcor kcalb sih ,deggurhs kcorB
,partskcoj eht hguorht kcoc s’trA ezeeuqs ot tnemom a gnikat ,dennirg kcorB
,drah-flah saw kcoc s’nogard eht deciton eh taht neht saw tI
ti revo gnicarg fo noitom ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,hsulb ylno dluoc torrap ehT
.moor gnignahc eht ot dekool eh sa ylsuoveihcsim gninnirg ,trA sdrawot denael eH
elkcub tleb sih didnu torrap eht ,siht htiW ”…did I ,haeY“
”!tser eht tuoba nialpmoc t’nac uoy ,gniyub er’eW“
saw tI .ylwols no ti gnitteg dna
,dehsulb trA ,siht htiw dnA
,esolc ni denael eH .kcorB dias
.srallod ytxis nogard eht gnidnah dna tuo tellaw sih gnillup erofeb
,sllib rallod nwo sih htiw tnuoma taht gninibmoc erofeb ,delims nogard ehT
.elkna s’trA dnuora gnilruc liat sih
:noitisop siht morf eltneg yrev erew ereh stsurht ehT
,kcorB ta kool ot denrut eH
.gnihtyreve tsniaga tsartnoc ot dewolla saw partskcoj eht taht os
.ylsuovren dnuohdoolb eht ta devaw torrap ehT
.llew sa ti gnidaenk
”,ereht ,llew sa yllufituaeb ssa ruoy semarf ti dnA“
.ti no tnemmoc ot ecnahc a evah dluoc kcorB erofeb ylkciuq stnap sih pord dluoc eh erus ekam ot detnaw eh ti lortnoc dluoc torrap eht fi tub
erew keehc sih no snroh meg kcalb eht railimaf woh gnizilaer ,deknilb mailliW
”.dednah-ytpme nwot evael mih tel annog t’nsaw I ,llew ,dna olleh yas ot nwod emac eh tub ,notsoB ni tuo sevil eh yllausU“ .nogard eht dias
,ni saw eh sa noos sa naom laruttug a tuo tel trA
.sgniht fo skool eht yb ,noitanretsnoc taerg s’torrap eht ot hcum
.worc ygdup tahwemos a yb revo dehctaw erew smoor gnignahc eht taht deciton eh dehcaorppa trA sa dna
.smoor gnisserd eht ta gnikool dna niaga daeh sih gnitfil erofeb
.worc eht ta dekniw kcorB
,ecnartne rehto eht morf ni emac taht
.ni emoc ot yppah yllaer saw eh taht llet dluoc eh tub
.edis eht ot denrut torrap ehT ”…mhU“
pirg sih tsujda kcorB gniees
.partskcoj nwo s’nogard eht otno dekael dah ti fo emos denigami eh dna
:daeh sih ot emac thguoht ralugnis eno ,emit taht tA
.elbanigami nirg gnitae-tihs tseggib eht dah eh taht was eh nogard eht ta dekool eh sa dna
.dneirf torrap sih ot derutseg neht eH
,saw ereht naht ssenisub erom hcum eb dluow ereht taht detcepxe eh
.nogard eht ot gninrut erofeb ,deggurhs tsuj dnuohdoolb ehT
.thguoht ni nihc sih gnibbur erofeb
”!ereh revo teG“ .detuohs eh ”!traB“
.egdir eye na desiar eh sa gniggurhs
,ni emoc remotsuc dnoces eht was eh erofeb
”.yas uoy revetahW“
.uoy rof spartskcoj fo sriap erom emos tuo kcip ew retfa leef uoy woh ees ll’eW“
.torrap eht dias ”,teb I“
seye sih gninepo erofeb ,rorrim eht tsniaga dnah eno decarb eH
nwod gnileenk erofeb ,dennirg kcorB
,hcneb eht tsniaga ecarb ylno dluoc trA
”!yad doog a evah uoy epoh I“
.hcamots etihw taht ta kool retteb a teg dluoc eh os ylthgils noitisop sih gnitsujda
.trA fo tuo psag prahs a ward ot ecrof hguone htiw ecno torrap eht otni gnitsurht
,spih s’trA debbarg ylpmis nogard ehT
.yletaidemmi pu gnizies srehtaef liat sih
.kcorB ot ti gnidnah dna partskcoj elprup a gnibbarg dna
,dennirg eh ,dnoces a retfA
.noitisiuqca wen siht htiw ton yllaicepse
.nwod dewob daeh sih htiw dias worc eht
.gnilims ,deilper nogard eht
.neerg fo edahs rethgil a dah taht htolc htiw partskcoj a pu gnikcip erofeb
…a fo tib a erew smoor gnignahc sih taht tpecxe ,lleW“
”.nehw kcab yaw ,ecalp
.edis eht morf partskcoj a gnillup
”.ereh ni lla ti tog ev’I ,yrrow t’noD“
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.htolc eht no neerg fo edahs eht ta gnikool ,deddon trA
,yaw eht fo tuo srehtaef daeh sih dehsurb eH
”,nwot fo tuo morf s’eH“
,nogard eht ta kcab dekool eH
.reisae ni edils ot htgnel taht gnipleh erp eht
,edis eno ot srehtaef osrot s’trA dehsurb eh ,dnah eno htiW
.eugnot s’kcorB tsniaga gnisserp flesmih dnuof eh sa mih fo tuo gnisruoc naom wol eht
N“ .yletaidemmi dehsulb trA ”!kcorB-B“
,drawrof trA desserp nogard eht ,siht htiW
”…uoy kcuf I sa uoy hctaw ot tnaw I“
”.kcab uoy yap ot tsuJ“ .dias eh ”,ereH“
.redrah dna retsaf ni gnimoc stsurht sih
.txen gnimoc saw tahw gnitapicitna fi sa
----**---- .srehtaef keehc sih hguorht wohs ot nageb hsulb eht sa
.ni kcab gnitsurht erofeb
.weiv ni yltnenimorp rehtar gnisir ydaerla loot eht
.tuhs seye sih dezeeuqs eH ”!kcuF“
.nogard eht dias ”,od I“
.dekil eh partskcoj neerg a gniees erofeb
,pohs eht detixe nogard dna torrap ,siht htiw dnA
:did ti taht seraw eht ni tlaed taht erots a rof regral rehtar saw ti ,sediseb dnA
.em htiw hcuot ni teg esaelp
,flesti otni taerter ot deirt ti yaw eht deton eH
,delims neht eH .dias eh ”,seY“
.taorht sih ni deid fo kniht dluoc trA esnopser ylno ehT
,siht ta dennirg kcorB
,torrap eht dniheb doots kcorB ”…seod tI“
:remit a nageb osla eh ,dnim sih nI
”.uoy teem ot dooG“ .dias eh ”,ih ,hU“
,yaw eht ni gnitteg saw ti tniop taht ta
retsiger eht ot emoc dluow enoemos yllautneve
eb ot gnitteg syawla ni tsurht eht
,erad ton dluow yeht
tooB dna pihW fo rohtua
.eb dluow yeht thguoht torrap eht sa evisurtni sa ton erew sparts kcalb eht dna
B“ .srehtaef keehc der sih tsap wohs ot gniganam hsulb eht
.dias eh ”,revetahW“
”.neerg ecaf ym ton ,neerg taht ot ti hctam retteb I sseug I“
”…em ot krow eht lla evael dna kcab nael tsuJ“
.yrruFoS dna ytiniffaruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,pohs eht ni repeeD
.ecaf s’torrap eht ni
meht fo deeps dna ssenhguor eht dna
.daeh sih koohs kcorB
!…haaA“ .citarre gniworg stsurht sih
.retsaf flesmih ekorts ot nageb eh sa mih fo edisni kcorB dloh ot gel sih gnisu ,yltneg tuo denaom eH
,revewoh ,eglub s’torrap eht eporg ot nwod dnah rehto eht dehcaer eh sA
,noisacco eno naht erom no smoor gnignahc eht no ti gnitteg nogard eht draeh dah eH
.deretne eh sa pu gnithgil seye teloiv sih
.kcorB ta dekool eh sa
.nepo yllaitrap gniniamer kaeb sih
”?eh nac ,won ,ecalp a gnieb morf taht pots yllaer t’nac eh ,sediseB“
.tsurht hcae htiw detaludnu ylleb etihw sih yaw eht ees torrap eht gnittel
,yawa denrut torrap ehT
.stnap sih fo tuo gnippets ydaerla kcorB gniees ,nwod dekool eH
.ssa s’torrap eht ot esolc gninael elzzum sih
,mih no doog rehtar dekool ti
.ylhguor ni spih sih gnimmals ,dennirg eH .deksa eh
,deddon torrap ehT
.tlih eht ot nwod yaw eht lla yaw sih dekrow eh erofeb kcoc kciht sih ot desu saw torrap eht erus gnikam
”.oot eseht fo tser eht ekat ll’ew ,kceh eht tahw dnA“
.ecnartne yhself s’torrap eht was eh sa gninnirg
.worc eht ot gniddon ,deilper kcorB ”,traB yeH“ .smoor gnignahc eht ot meht gnirutseg erofeb
.ylsuoveihcsim gninnirg
.gninnirg ,mih ta dekniw torrap ehT .deksa kcorB
”,drib elttil ,won thgir uoy rof hguone ysae s’taht ,thgirlA“
.edis eht ot daeh sih detlit mailliW ti dehctaw eh sa dna
niaga daeh s’kcorB dniheb dnah a gnignirb
”!moor gnignahc eht hctaw yug a gnivah yb ti no nwod raeb t’nod I tsael ta ,yeH“
.ylsuovren ni dehtaerb dna kcab pets a koot eh sa
”?uoy t’nod ,taht ekil uoy ,haeY“ ”…nam
”.gnippohs ecin a evaH“ .dias eh ”,dooG“
.sredluohs sih no dnah a gnicalp yltneg ,trA ot dekool neht eH .dias eh
.hcaorppa nogard eht dehctaw eh sa daeh sih gnikahs ,delahxe eH
”,torrap ,kcab ruoy nO“
----**---- ”?yawyna meht rof yap ot evah d’ew taht gniht dab a hcus yllaer taht sI“
”,em rehtob t’nseod tI“ .deggurhs kcorB
,llaw sih ot kcab denrut neht eH ”.uoy
.dias eh ”,ris ,yas uoy revetahW“
,snoitartsinim sih rednu naom torrap eht draeh eh sa dennirg eH
”…em edisni kcoc taht evol gnikcuf I“
”.ti tuoba nainocard nettog sah eno siht tuB“
.no partskcoj a dellup ylkciuq redro trohs ni dna
,kcab daeh sih werht torrap ehT ”!haaaA“
.dnah s’kcorB ni spartskcoj eht ot gnikool erofeb
,drawrof denael neht kcorB
,s’kcorB sdrawot devom yletaidemmi dnah s’trA dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.stsurht fo mhtyhr retsaf tahwemos a htiw gnitrats erofeb
”.hguoht ,seye ruoy fo edahs eht hctam dluow siht kniht I“
”?huh ,ereh thgir ti tnaw uoY“ .dias eh ”…sey-
,denepeed ylno hsulb s’torrap ehT
?!taht yojne eh diD
gninrut yletaidemmi erofeb ,siht ta delggig eH .deilper eh
,deifisnetni hsulb s’torrap ehT
,naom a elfits ot dah torrap ehT
.yltneg daeh sih fo edis eht gnikcil
dna keehcssa etisoppo eht ot
.deksa mailliW ”?thgir taht sI“
”.torrap raed ym ,dnammoc uoy sA“
.partskcoj eht yb demarf saw ti sa ssa s’torrap eht gnirimda dna
.nam a fo nemiceps a etiuq osla saw eh taht yned ton dluoc torrap eht dna
,delkcuhc kcorB ,ereh dnA
”!uoy gnimalb m’I neht ,selur eht gnikaerb elpoep ni stluser llits siht fi dnA
.gnitsurht sih htiw emit ni sekorts wef a ti gnivig
.ni kcab yaw eht lla gnitsurht erofeb ,trA fo tuo yletelpmoc llup kcorB was stsurht esehT
,ylper dluoc torrap eht erofeB
.dnuoh eht ta kcab yllacitegolopa gnicnalg torrap eht
”?huh ,klaw ynnuf a htiw retsiger hsac taht ot kcab klaw uoy ekam ot em tnaW“
.ydaer saw eh gnitacidni
,delkcuhc trA .deilper kcorB
.kcen s’trA fo srehtaef eht no yltneg elbbin ot gninrut erofeb
,tahwemos osrot s’kcorB derevoc esruoc fo srehtaef liat siH
,lausu sa dehsilop demees selacs siH
.daeh etihw a dna srehtaef keehc telracs htiw torrap neerg a eno siht
stsurht fo ecap retsaf ehT
”?gniod uoy era tahW
.dnah sih otni gniglub kcoc naiva egral taht leef ot desirprus yltnasaelp saw eh
.niaga rekcup knip taht tsap gnihsurb eugnot sih
etsatsid delaecnoc-ylerab fo ria na deniatnoc eciov s’mailliW
,spartskcoj dleh yeht sdnah rieht nI
,rorrim eht otni decnalg trA
,ecalp ni selur eht lla htiw
,lla retfa ,edirP gnirud ssenisub tsom eht tog syawla yehT
.rennacs eht gniffins
,tsurht laturb eno ni
.mih detpurretni nogard eht ”,eseht ekil ew ,em tsurT“
,detlih eh sa gel s’torrap eht tsniaga osrot sih gnisserp
”…annog m’I …m’I …kcorB
”—eht fo erac ekat ew taht owt uoy dnimer ot deen I od netfo woH“
,kcezzoW rreH yb ”pirT gnippohS“
”.uoy raeh meht tel retteb uoY“ .dias eh
,edis eht ot decnalg worc ehT
.ereht ni thgiarts
.wor eht ni tsehtruf moor gnisserd eht ot trA gnidael
.tsrif tuo yrt dluohs eh partskcoj hcihw tuo gnirugif ydaerla saw nogard elprup eht ,mih dniheb rood eht desolc dah eh sa noos sA
,ylthgils seye sih deworran nogard ehT
”?he ,taht ekil uoy kcuf em gnihctaw ekil uoy ,haeY“
”…ecnatsni rehtona rof taht evas dluohs I“
.dias eh ”,od uoy haey kcuF“
.yllufituaeb ssa sih demarf ti yaw eht tsuj dna
.ffo htolc eht fo emos gnipiw htolc eht
,ni dekcud neht eH ”.esruoc fO“
”!yug gib ,em ot ti eviG“
,llew sa ffo trihs sih gnillup erofeb ,delahxe neht eH
.no ti gniyrt elpoep rof
.ees ot kcorB detnaw yllaer torrap eht taht gnihtemos ton saw no-drah gnigar sih
.kcab daeh sih dellup eh sa
”?tnaw uoy od kcits fo dnik tahW“
”.pohs ruo ot emoclew ,olleH“
.lleb erots eht fo gnignir eht yb eirever sih fo tuo dekconk neht saw
”,su no lufituaeb kool yeht dna ,tif yeht ,meht deirt ew
.kcorB ta kcab decnalg eh
”?thgir ,uoy ta gniralg saw eh woh thguac uoy erus m’I ,naem I
,sllab sih ni gut railimaf taht ta ,neht dnA
,mih no ecin rehtar dekool yeht ,lla ni llA
,partskcoj eht fo tuo kcoc nwo sih dellup ylkciuq eH
,taht ekorts ot detrats eh dna
.redluohs s’trA fo kcab eht no gnisserp erofeb
”…hpmM …hpmM“ .gnileef eht ni gnikat dna
,drawrof denael neht eH
,delims kcorB ”…hooO …s’tahT“
.gnihtyna yas dluoc dnuoh eht erofeb
,yltcaxe srehtaef sih dehctam htolc neerg fo edahs ehT .dne eht ni
,hcneb eht fo ffo thgir mih kcor ot denetaerht
.sredluohs sih revo dekool ylno torrap ehT
,ni denael nogard eht tuB ”!--s’tahT“
.ecaf s’torrap eht fo edis eht gnikcil
.nib eht ot derutseg eH .deilper traB
,hA“ .kcab daeh sih werht torrap eht
,kcab daeh sih werht neht eH ”!haaaaA
,dnah sih ni skeehc ssa eht dedaenk eH .deunitnoc kcorB
.niaga mih gniretne kcoc s’kcorB fo erusserp railimaf eht fo erawa saw eh neht dna
.xes fo ksum thgil eht dellems eh sa tuo gninaom ,deyebo trA .ylhguor ni kcab gnitsurht dna kcab gnillup erofeb ,dias eh ”,yob ,ti ffinS“
.eugnot sih no nwod tib eh sa erusaelp ni deddil-flah seye sih
.retsiger hsac eht ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut eh ,siht htiw dnA
:pu kcip dluow ssenisub yllautneve taht erus saw eh dna
”.ssa sih ni kcits eht htiw renwo taht lla fo tsael ,ees nac ydobon taht erehwemos ebyaM“
”.yawyna eseht gnitteg ylbaborp m’I“
.reganam sih ta dekool eh sa smra sih gnissorc ,drawrof deppets worc eht ,os dnA
,timda ot dah torrap ehT
.uoy morf raeh ot evol d’I dna
.hcneb eht ot gnikool erofeb ,kcorB ta pu kcab dekool torrap ehT ”…haeY“
,moor gnignahc eht fo edisni saw torrap eht sa noos sA
.sragnah eht ffo nekat neeb dah yeht taht deciton eh hguoht
.dias eh ”,ti s’tahT“
.mih ta dekniw nogard elprup eht tuB
sdnah s’torrap eht dna sih htob ni spartskcoj eht lla gnittup ,ylkciuq devom eH
dnuoh ehT ?yas ot evah eh dluow tahw neht dna
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
”.siht lla ekat ’nikcuF“
,neht yb pu deps dah stsurht s’nogard ehT
.eireganeM oirT fo rebmem a dna
”?neppah siht tel uoy dluoc woH“
.kcab daeh sih dellup eh sa kaeb sih fo tuo gnillol eugnot sih
.gniws lluf ni gnieb edirP htiw tahw
ecaf s’traB no noisserpxe eht hctac ot teg ton did trA ”.tseb ehT“
eh erehw ,noertaP sih no erom neve dnif nac uoY
.mih dniheb nogard eht ta dekool eh sa ylthgils sgel sih gnitsujda
.ssa s’trA dezeeuqs yltneg dna nwod dehcaer neht ti erofeb ,dnoces a rof ereht deregnil dnah ehT
,enuJ ni ylralucitraP
.mih otni tsurht ot egarevel retaerg flesmih evig ot ylthgils teef sih gnitsujda
.kcab daeh sih dial eh detnap trA sa dna
,kcab eht ni erew smoor gnignahc s’erots ehT
.noitcelfer sih ta gnikool dna
,yawyna hguone noos ti ees dluow nogard eht ebyaM
.resolc gninael ,dennirg kcorB ”…kcorB ,esaelP“
,srehtaef liat sih desiar yltbus neht eH
,deksa kcorB ”?haeY“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
pu dnah rehto sih gnignirb erofeb ,siht ta nirg ylno dluoc nogard ehT
.ecaf s’torrap eht ot ti gnidloh dna
pu kcab partskcoj eht gnikcip
.eeyolpme sih ta ylgninetaerht gniralg ,retnuoc eht revo denael neht eH ”!niagA“ .dias eh
”.meht no spartskcoj fo tol a evah did yehT“
.seinnep dna ,semid ,sretrauq ni egnahc tcaxe gnicudorp erofeb retnuoc eht no ereht thgir meht gnivael
.hcneb eht ot derutseg kcorB erofeb gnol tiaw ot evah ton did eh tub
.ecaf s’trA ni partskcoj eht bur ot nageb nogard eht sa ecaf sih tsniaga ti gnidloh
.keehc ssa taht daenk ot nageb nogard eht sa yltneg ni gnihtaerb
,ni dehtaerb eh erofeb eloh taht no avilas fo ytnelp evael ot erus gnikam
,ylkciuq taht yksum taht nettog dah partskcoj eht woh ksa yllaer ot emit dah eh erofeB
”.yxes ,ydaer eb retteb uoY“
,ereht ni dleh neht eH
.ecalp ni spih s’trA dleh dna dellup yeht sa
”?taht wonk uoy ,etuc yllaer er’uoY“
”,eno doog yrev a gnivah m’I ,hO“
.siht ekil s’oiranecs otni desae eb ot dedeen trA taht wenk eh
,deretsulf ylbidercni dekool torrap ehT
”…noitseuq eno sevael taht oS“
,mih ta dekniw kcorB
.eugnot s’kcorB otno dnirg ot nageb eh sa
”.ereh syob doog tub gnihton er’ew wonk uoY“
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.tsiaw s’kcorB dnuora ti gnipparw dna pu gel eerf sih gnitfil erofeb deddon trA ”…annog …annoG“
,lla retfA“ .dennirg eH
.yadrutaS remmus a rof ,yad wols yllausunu na saw tI
”.snoitca rieht ni meht thguac I kniht t’nod I“
:pohs eht no hctaw sih tpek dnuohdoolb redlo ylevitaler eht ,llitS
.tuo gnillup yletaidemmi
”.xat sulp ,74.021$ eb ll’tahT“ .daeh sih tsniaga kcab gnidlof srae sih ,dehgis mailliW
,dennirg kcorB ”…erom ees em tel ,esaelP
.lairetam eht rof gnileef dna ni gnihcaer erofeb
.dnah sih ni sregnah partskcoj eht ta nwod gnikool erofeb noitcelfer nwo sih ni tseretni esnetni na gnikat
.dnim ni erup naht ssel gnihtemos dah nogard eht taht gnileef a dah eh
edisni yaw eht lla tsurht eh sa kcorB ta pu gnikool ,tuo denaom eH
.niaga ecnartne s’torrap eht ta gnippal ,dennirg kcorB
.keehc sih no shtworgtuo ekil-kcor kcalb eht fo eno gnippat ,deddon eH
,yletaidemmi tsomlA
,emit emas eht dnuora thgir pu dekcip gnitsurht ehT
doog tsuJ .oot ,llew ytterp sehcterts ti ekil skool tI“
:esruoc fo ,yadot neppah ton dluow siht erus saw eH
.dettimda eh ”,eurt s’tahT“
,moor gnignahc eht ni kcab eb dluow nogard taht ,yllautneve taht wenk eh
.torrap eht ot derutseg worc ehT
.llit eht tsniaga denael eh sa drah gnimlapecaf ,siht ta denaorg mailliW
Y“ .s’kcorB no tser ot gnimoc sdnah sih fo eno
.gnilkcuhc ,yltneg ni detsurht eH .dias eh
,stnap sih no reppiz dna nottub eht dna
.ycnegru fo tnuoma doog a htiw htgnel s’kcorB tsniaga gnidnirg ,deilper torrap eht ”,haey wA“
.mih fo tuo snaom erom werd
”.yad doog a gnivah er’uoy epoH“
.pley teiuq rehtar a tuo gnittel
:dehgis mailliW ,siht tA
,ni detsurht eh ,siht htiw dnA
retfa noos gniwollof tsehc sih
.elprup thgil eht gniees dna ti ta gnikool erofeb ,deddon kcorB
”?uoy od ,ereht htlif rof daer teg ot tnaw t’noD“
.erom neve sgel sih gnidaerps ,seye sih desolc torrap ehT ”…seY“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.emit
,moor gnignahc eht ni sremotsuc ylurnu rehto morf llew oot lla wenk eh eno saw ti ,revewoh
”…ti s’tahT …kcorB ,haey kcuf hO“
.retsaf dna rehguor neve worg stsurht s’kcorB tlef eh sa ysatsce ni naom ylno dluoc torrap eht tub
.sllaw eht dnuora lla gnuh taht spartskcoj eht ot noitnetta sih denrut yllanif trA
.dnuoh eht ta pu gnikool ,delims neht eH
”?thgir ,ezis tsiaw eht kcehc ot detnaw uoY“ .dias kcorB
.htaerb fo ekatni prahs a gnikat
nwod gnitfihs ylneddus srehtaef liat sih
,seye dnik htiw kcorB ot deddon eH
.repeed neve ni tsurht ot egarevel sa gel sih dloh sdnah s’kcorB fo eno gnileef ,denaom trA
,siht htiw eltneg yrev saw eH
”,sdneped taht ,lleW“
,ylduol rehtar tuo denaom trA ”…haey hO“
,tif doog a eb dluow kniht uoy yrots trohs a evah uoy fi dnA
.tnemhsilbatse eht fo rood eht sdrawot gninrut erofeb ,reihsac eht ta dennirg nogard ehT ”!uoy knahT“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
tsiaw s’torrap eht no pirg sih gnimrofer ,dennirg kcorB
noitats s’mailliW yb thgir gab a ni meht gnippord dna dnah sih ni spartskcoj owt eht gninnacs ylkciuq ,drawrof denael neht eH
:tnadnetta eno ylno dah smoor gnignahc s’pohs eht dalg saw eH
s’trA gnikcil ,drawrof denael neht eH
,noitatiseh emos htiw deretne dna hsulb ylthgils a dah eH
.torrap eht ot gnikool erofeb ,delkcuhc nogard ehT ”…I-I“ .dias eh ”!kcorB-
.nogard elprup eht desserdda eh sa
.ylivaeh hsulf flesmih gnileef
.gnitam rieht fo trap reilrae eht fo ksum eht ni gnikat
:dehcaorppa sremotsuc fo riap a sa dehctaw eh ,neht dnA
,margeleT dna rettiwT no yggodikahk@ m’I
.yltruc deddon mailliW
.hgual nogard eht was mailliW nehw rood eht tuo htob erew yehT
.emit emos rof esaeler rof gniggeb neeb dah kcoc nwo sih dna
,ytpme gnileef fo noitasnes eht ta denaorg trA
”?taht tuoba ddo gnihtyna eciton t’ndid uoY“
.torrap eht ta daeh sih gnikahs
.yltbus sgel sih gnidaerps ,yltneg delahxe eH ”…kcuuuuF“ .ylesnemmi denedrah kcoc sih sa nethgit partskcoj sih gnileef ,llaw eht tsniaga rehtruf denael eH
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.dnah eht no nwod gnizeeuqs yltneg
.yletaidemmi deksa mailliW
.dekrims nogard ehT
,gnidnirg eltneg s’kcorB otni dekcub ylthgil osla eH
”?ssa ym pu kcits a teg I gnitseggus er’uoY“
.fo ffo emac partskcoj eht taht regnah eht gnikat erofeb ,delims neht eH
.pu deeps ot nugeb dah stsurht s’kcorB taht deciton eh ,yltniaF
!tey esoht thguob neve t’nevah eW“ .dias eh ”!kcorB“
.gnidnammoc dna wol enot sih ,dias eh
,mih nihtiw kcoc kciht eht tsniaga kcab dehsup torrap ehT
,drawrof denael neht kcorB
.trA dias ”,ton sseug I“
----**---- …mih no lausunu gnihtyna dellems eh fi dnA .wot ni torrap taht htiw
.ni gnihtaerb dna
.meht fo owt eht ta daeh sih gnikahs ,niaga dehgis eH
,taebtraeh gnidnuop sih mlac ot delahni eH
,dehsulb torrap ehT
.ssa s’torrap eht tsniaga pu spih sih gnidnirg
,tuhs seye sih dezeeuqs torrap ehT
”?os kniht uoy t’noD“
.cisum secudorp osla
”,luaPuR tniop noitamalcxE“
”?deid dna ssa sih pu delwarc tahw oS“
,stnap sih deppord eh ,os dnA
.dias eh ”,flesruoy rof kaepS“
,dias eh ”,hcum os ti dnim t’ndid renwo tsal ehT“
,tsrif ni emac nogard elprup a
,drawrof denael neht eH
”?ti t’nsi ,ssa ecin a thgilhgih ot hguone
,ylgnisaet deksa kcorB
.eporg yldneirf yrev a ssa sih gnivig ,torrap eht ta dehcaer eh ,siht htiW
.deksa eh ”?os kniht uoY“
.esolc torrap eht dleh eh sa daeh s’trA ot esolc gninael ,deksa kcorB
.niaga aera s’reihsac eht gnitcepsni ,dehgis mailliW pirT gnippohS  kcezzoWrreH yb ”pirT gnippohS“   :yojne esaelP
.llew sa ti gnihcterts erofeb ,dnah nwo sih ni partskcoj eht ot denrut eH
”…drah em kcuF“ .dias eh
,dekool nogard eht yaw eht tuoba esle gnihtyreve dethgilhgih tsuj partskcoj eht tuB
”.srehtaef ydob eht ot ti hctam ot gniog er’uoy fi ,em ot ekil-edaj erom mees uoY“
,torrap eht morf naom sselhtaerb a werd
,delahxe torrap ehT
.dias eh ”,onnud I“
”,teiuq rehtar erew yeht ,ris ,yrroS“
.yltneg osrot s’trA nwod dna pu bur ot gnitrats sdnah sih
,eman s’nogard elprup eht tuo dnuof reven d’eh
.kcorB fo tnorf ni partskcoj a gnihcterts erofeb ,denrut neht eH
.ylpmis deddon worc ehT
.ecaf s’torrap eht fo edis eht dekcil eh sa
”—tuohtiw yrgna teg annog er’yeht wonk ,hu uoY“
.teef sih otno gnitteg erofeb ,dekrims eh ,siht deciton eh sa dna
,skeehc ssa owt eht detrap eh ,ereH
.nogard elprup eht ta pu dekool eh sa gnihsulf ecaf sih
,delkcuhc kcorB sa dehctaw eH
,kcar nwo sih ot kcab denrut neht eH
”.kcorB ,syawla sA“ ”.lausu sa teiuQ“
”pirT gnippohS“ saw sihT
”…ereh thgir ,em kcuF“
.deldniwd dah taht sraey eht revo tub
”.uoy rof neerg krad elttil A …mH“
.ecnartne s’torrap eht ta kcoc gnikael sih gninoitisop
.mih erofeb nogard eht was eh sa noos sa ni gnihtaerb ,denrut trA
.ni gnitsurht ylwols ot emac ti nehw emit teews sih koot kcorB tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ylsuovren delkcuhc torrap ehT ”…hu ,oS“
.nruter nogard eht dna torrap eht was eh sa noos sa pu dekrep mailliW
”?ni selcsum esoht gniees ekiL“
.ydob sih ffo gniwohs ,ffo trihs nwo sih dellup neht eH
,seraw sih fo duorp rehtar saw eh
.stnap sih ot nwod gnikool erofeb
”!em kcuf ,kcorB ,esaelP“
.og ew ereht ,peY“
,mra s’kcorB ot pu dnah a thguorb eH
,stsurht fo mhtyhr llams a nageb eH
,delworg kcorB ”…ybab ,haeY“
skeehc sih ot gnihsur taeh eht
sdnirg wols sih htiw emit sih gnikat
”…haey wA“ .deksa kcorB
:llems egnarts rehtar a pu dekcip eh ,yletaidemmI
.nogard eht dias ”,gniht lacigol ylno ehT“
,deddon ylsselhtaerb trA
”?he ,ydaerla ti nettog ev’dluow yeht teb I ,hO“ .revo gninrut
.drawrof denael eH
ragnah sti morf spartskcoj eht fo eno gnippilcnu erofeb ,dneirf naiva sih ta dekniw nogard eht ,nwod tneb eh sA
,pu kcab tas trA ,yletaidemmI
.mailliW dias ”,dooG“
.detcepxe evah dluow eh naht gnissapmocne-lla erom
.srehtaef keehc
”,smoor gnisserd eht ni gnikcuf elpoep erew erehT“ .deksa eh ”?ris ,ti si tahW“
”.melborp gib on s’ti oS“
”?esle tahW“ ”?sruoy fo dneirF“
”.selur moor gnignahc eht wonk uoY“
,delahni torrap ehT ”…ti llemS“
.yawa denrut eh sa ni gnihtaerb
,pih sih otno edils dnah s’kcorB tlef trA ”…deedni seod tI“
,srehtaef sih pu edir partskcoj eht tlef eh nehw saw tahT
partskcoj eht morf ksum eht ni gnihtaerb
.ni kcab gnitsurht dna tuo gnillup erofeb ,ylpeed delkcuhc kcorB
,kcab sgel sih evohs kcorB tlef eh
”.hctaw emuser dna ereht kcab teg woN“
.resolc mih gnirb ot
,siht ta naorg ylno dluoc torrap ehT
”?ereht ni erew yeht gnol woh eciton t’ndid uoY“
gnikrow selcsum mra s’kcorB ees llits dluoc eh tub
”?huh ,tuls drib elttil ytrid a hcuS“
.resolc mih gnillup dna
.revo dekool nogard eht tub