.ria fo wolftuo tfos a gnileef
sbmurcdaerb ekil gnippord neeb d'ehs seroc evisolpxe elttil fo enil eht fo dne eht ta pots ot
.renroc txen eht dnuora ilA gnidnif ,ykcul
,tesolc a naht reggib hcum ton moor depmarc a ot denepo tI
.enog efil elohw reh rof nrow d'ehs taht ralloc eht
.snoitasrevnoc ruo ot gninetsil neve ebyam
,rallip siht tsniaga pu delruc
,stik rof dezis stoc ytpme owt htiw
,hctah gnisolc eht htaenrednu drows latem lluh sih deppils eh ,tsaf gniknihT
.ylgnihtoos dias eh ",won esolc
,kcen reh fo ruf dettam
,ediw retem a tuoba etercorref fo erauqs a dettops I ,hguone erus dna
draeh I sa ,kniht ot em fo suolucidir saw hcihW
,tuo si nepo ti gniyrp ,lleW"
.flesym ot woh-wonk lacirtcele ym lla tpek I fi retteb eb dluow ti semitemoS
eht rof si eciveD tnemegaruocsiD emuloV s'693-256# tinU ecivreS"  ".kcen reh ffo ralloc denmad taht stnaw tsuj ehS
.yromem eht yb detnuah dekool seye
,sevlehs erom erew ereht edisnI
.semit eerht ,eciwt
tuoba decaps srallip etercorref fo sniamer eht gniwollof
",ereh teg ot sraey net detiaw ev'eW"
.sseug I ,enif s'tahT"
sdem eruzies-itna fo laiv a tuo dellup dna em morf ti koot aimaH
,deerga I ",esnes sekaM"
,etihw detniap erew sllaw ehT
",neht drawrof og ew sseuG"
.thgil VU a htiw hcrot cirtcele na gnibbarg
"?si ytilicaf anihcaM xaP eht erehw etalugnairt ot tnempiuqe ym gnisu yrt ot em tnaw uoY"
.kcab emoc ot em rof gnillac anihcaM xaP rebmemer llits I .deredduhs ehS
.knuht sselohce ,dilos a htiw ti tih selkcunk yM
,enO raeY :tcejorP noitamalceR ehT
yojne esaelP  .noitarepsed dna
d'ew taht ,raef eno yM
,dnuora denrut ehS
,hctah eht morf yawa deppets ehs sa revoc rof dekcud I dna aimaH nehT .moor ylbmessa eht morf llah eht nwod deklaw d'ew sa
".rehtie ffiks eht fo kcab eht ni hcrotwolb
yldognu uoy ,reh hcuot ton oD"
gnihtyna ees uoy od ,eoJ"
.niarts ot deunitnoc eh sa kcen sih no elbisiv snodnet eht ,detnurg eh "…latem …ytiC"
.elkcunk sih htiw rallip eht gnippat dna ffiks eht fo tuo flesmih gnillup ,dias eh
,derad I sa raf sa pu flesym dellup I
retnec eht ta thgil der eht ,kcen reh dnuora gnir latem eht gnilaever
t'ndluoc I dna ,seod ilA"
,nwo reh fo htob ni dnah s'drazil eht gnippirg
"?siht ezingocer uoy oD"
.repsihw a naht ssel ,slebiced ytnewt sa wol sa sdnuos tceted ot elba spahrep
,pil reh gniwehc ,niaga deddon ilA
.ylsuoiraorpu gnihgual
nerdlihc fo gnignirbpu eht gninrecnoc srettam no ecnarongi yM"
,detanoted sevisolpxe eht sa spmuhw-
,daer taht ngis a fo sniamer dedorroc-yldab
,kaolc sih ni reh depparw dna ilA pu dekcip aimaH # # # .smra
.edis ruoy ta drows ym htiw
.sdradnats
,noisserpxe reh morF
".deneppah gnihtemos fi uoy pleh ot elba eb ton dluow I .ton dluoc I tub
,drows sih htiw hsurbrednu eht hguorht gnippohc ,tniop koot aimaH .sehsub eldeen wol
,peels s'nexiv gnuoy eht revo gnihctaw
,tnev eht ta revo gnitrats ,deddon ilA
",ylbaborp ,yllacisyhP"
a evag neht ,ecaf reh no nworf peed a htiw dnuora gnikool
dna htaehs sti morf drows eguh ylsuolucidir taht werd eH
.ni thguorb eb dluoc gnidliub
,revo detrats dna kcab deklaw neht
,tsalb eht fo tsom debrosba
"!noitar eirolac txen ruoy nrae ot tfihs krow ruoy etelpmoc esaelP" .ydob sti dnuora yllauqe decaps
.nopaew sih gnisiar ,aimaH dias
rieht gnitelpmoc retfa devom neeb dah stik eht denoitnem anihcaM xaP nehW"
.htuom ym tfel ti sa neve yas ot saw ti gniht suolucidir a tahw dezilaer I "?ereht uoY"
gniylf htob I dna ilA gnidnes ,detanoted tI
,em ta dennirg ehS  .reh deksa I
",krow t'ndid taht lleW"
.niaga dednuos peelb eht litnu htrof dna kcab ti gnivom ylwols
.rewsna eht fo diarfa erew ehs fi sa
a spahrep ,edis hcae no sretemitnec evif
kool denrecnoc a degnahcxe aimaH
,duola detuohs dna htuom reh denepo ehs ,pots reh ekam ot stsirw reh debbarg eh nehW
”.gnireffus reh dne ot
,sebut egral lareves erew sllaw eht gnolA
.tuo yaw ym dnuof dna
hcnerw elttil a elots I
.doog ytterp gnileef llits saw I tub
,ereht hguorht lwarc thgim ilA
.feiler ni gnibbos ,em degguh tsuj dna sdrow tnerehoc mrof ot gniyrt pu evag ehS …s'tI
rood eht dna reh neewteb gnimoc ,reh fo tnorf ni deleenk aimaH   .revo dna revo
.aimaH hguorht derewsna ehs
,elbaima era uoy fi
.deddon dna yltfos delbmur aimaH sa
tuo defoolf liat reh ,tinu eht ta derats ilA
"!ereht fo tuo teG
"?lla ta rebmemer uoy od ,ecalp siht saw gib woH"
".tcerroc si tahT"   .duola deksa I
".erom elttil a spahrep
,moorkrow egral a otni pu denepo hcihw yawrood a ni gnidnats saw ehS
,dias yllanif neht ,ylippahnu delbmur drazil eulb gib ehT
.eltsihw gnicreip-rae
.edistuo tog I nehw
.ylsuoiruf devaw sregnif dna swap
,moor ylbmessa eht dehcaer yeht sa
.tobor eht ta ti gnissot dna evisolpxe citsalp fo ebuc elttil eht gnibbarg ,elbat krow eht ot revo nar I
.ecaf reh no nirg ecreif a ,aimaH ot pu gnihtemos dengis dna em morf yawa dellup ilA
"?ti etavitca thgim taht
.gnar srae ym sa roolf eht ffo pu flesym gnikcip
.ezeens a htiw pu enog lla evah dluoc uoy dna
.esle gnihtyreve no eye na tpek aimaH dna ilA dna rekcart eht no eye na tpek I sa
.kcab ti gnidils ,modnar ta rood a nepo dellup I
dehtuom dna noisolpxe na demim ehS
detcaer ralloc s'ilA  "!oN"
!gnilgge hsiloof ,hsiloof uoy
,em fo tnorf ni tuo rotceted langis eht dleh I
.dnuof eb ot gnitiaw tsuj ytilicaf anihcaM xaP a tuoba remialC‘ elbillug a ot yrots a nips ot meht esu dluoc I fi erom ebyam ro ,raey a ylraen
,ti gnidliub er'uoy nehw hctiws gnorw eht pilf ro ,pu dexim gniriw eht teG" .deerga I ",haeY"
,evitca gniniamer ecalp siht fo aedi eht ekil t'nod I" .deksa aimaH
yllautca t'nseod 693-256# tinU ecivreS oS"
tnemom a rof thguoht ilA
,etarg eht ot revo ylluferac deklaw aimaH dna ilA sa snoitcerroc esruoc detuohs I ".yawa
",ni decitcarp llew m'I gnihtemos si ecrof eturB"
....fi ees ot evah tsuj ew woN" .reh dlot I
.mottob eht dehcaer ew litnu ,trid dna ssarg eht otni gniggid swalc ,nwod detoocs eW
rood eht nepo uoy dluoc ,taht od uoy erofeB"
.em ta deralg drazil eulb yrgna fo sretem flah a dna owt sa htuom ym tuhs I "—
.enim ton ,esitrepxe fo aera ruoy s'tahT"
erab eht gnihcuot
yawllah leets gnol a fo dne eht ta saw I
.ffiksrevoh eht ot derad ew sa tsaf sa kcab deggoj htob ew neht dna
,no tnew I ,tnemeerga ni deddon ehs nehW .deksa I
.htob meht dlot I
".tnafni na tsomla s'ehs s'elpoep ym yB
"?thgir taht t'nsi ,stnemngissa erom yna evah
,derepsihw ehs sa yhctarcs eciov reh
uoy gninraw fo yaw yna evah t'ndid I yrros m'I
.mih sdrawot nwod dehcaer selcatnet erom sa ,denraw anihcaM xaP ",segelivirp negyxo fo noitacover ni tluser yam stinu anihcaM xaP fo noitcurtseD"
s’aimaH ”…thgit oot steg
.swap reh htiw ti barg ot deirt ehs sa ,peeb yrgna na tuo tel dna dehsalf taorht reh ta thgil der ehT .yletaidemmi
,syad xiS .nruter neht dna
annog uoY"  ".niaga ytleurc hcus tpmetta ot ton thguat anihcaM xaP dna
”,nepo rood taht teg dna ,sloot thgir eht teg ll’eW“  ".noitpo
.edis eht nwod epirts der a htiw dekram eno htiw ti gnicalper dna enizagam eht gnivomer
saw ti yhw ,rof erew yeht tahw tuo erugif ot tnaw tsuj I"
.tfahs eht fo egde eht no gnittis ,dias I
,gnihsal liat sih ,gninepo eht fo tnorf eht ni htrof dna kcab gnicap ,tnemom a detiaw eH "!tuo emoc esaelP
".dnuora kool su pleh nac aimaH neht
,ni uoy teg ot em deen yam uoy
.edis rehtie no srood leets lareves htiw ,sthgil daehrevo yb til
,dna ereh su gnidael rof uoy yap esruoc fo lliw I
.dias eh ”,yrt nac ew esle gnihtyna s’ereht fi wonk ot stnaw ehS“
,ediw sretem evif spahrep kcart nevenu
.stiuspmuj etihw dezis tik htiw kcar a dna
.noitcnuj T a ni dedne hcihw ,llah eht fo dne eht ot ylteiuq drawrof deddap I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si ehT
.ecived eht gnikcehcer ,spets erom ruof koot dna seerged ytenin denrut neht
,ffo ralloc denmad taht teg ilA depleh d'I
…yllanoitomE" .dias eh
.dnif dluoc I eert tsellat eht pu bmilc ot detrats I sa ,dehgual aimaH "!era uoy oS"  "?rebmemer ,drapoel a m'I"
",kcol eht gnikcip si os dna
,su fo tnorf ni thgir saw yadretsey su detaefed dah taht hctah delgna ehT
.deriuqer si noituac yhw won ees tsum uoy tub ,ilA
eht ta deppots eW .laog ruo ot
.sevlehs strap eht morf eno rehtona debbarg I ,daeh reh koohs ehs nehW
.seirruf htiw yrotsih rieht gnirahs fo tibah eht ni t'nerew snamuH
dna ti nepo ew ecno ,ytilicaf eht fo stnetnoc eht fo egatnecrep a uoy reffo lliw ew
".devomer eb tonnac tI .ytilicaf siht fo ytefas
.regnif elgnis a pu dleh ehS
.reh erussaer ot deirt aimaH
.niaga lluh sti ffo decnuob tsuj eldeen tsrif ehT
.eromyna meht raew ot nosaer on eb dluow ereht
,drawrof ecap ot detrats
a tahw wonk neve t'ndid I
langis a tnes gnihtemoS"
,drawrof gniklaw detrats eW
.uoy eltrats did I spahrep
.dednamed aimaH "?tahW"  .peelb
dna dnuorg eht no ti gnittes ,redluohs ym morf xobloot ym gnulsnu I
.yoj fo poohw gniraor a tuo tel aimaH sa ,ediw werg seye reH
dna resolc deppets I
!ilA ,enod lleW"
,spets rellams gnikat
anihcaM xaP lap ruoY
.elbuort ni saw ehs fi neve tuo llac t'ndluoc ehS
.yawrood rehtona ta yruf teiuq ni gnirats saw ohw ,ilA otni pmub tsomla ot
,ediw retem eno yb gnol sretem owt
tahw wonk uoy oD"
rof tner ym yap ot hguone eb dluow stekcop reh ni revotfel dah d'ehs seroc evisolpxe nezod-flah gniniamer eht dna
.enigami t'ndluoc I daeh reh hguorht gniog sthguoht tahw
".noitcerid taht morf gnimoc s'tI"
,evitisnes yrev saw ti taht llet dluoc dna walc a htiw nepo eno deirp I
’!erew uoy ,seY‘ eht tub ,dias ehs tahw etalsnart t'ndluoc I
".tabmoc ni deniart ton era uoY" .dias aimaH
,sehctiws dna snottub
,ygrene htiw delkcarc ecafrus stI
",erus rof s'taht ,ereht  nwod evitca gnihtemos s'ereht ,lleW"
.tnip driht ym ffo dehsinif I sa
.ylflesmaD eht ta sknird fo dnuor a derahs dna
"?neht egarots mret gnol si erehw oS"
,yrotimrod eht ni eno eht sa ediw sa eciwt yawllah a otni tuo del tI
.daeha pu eltsihw gnirewsna reh
",raf siht emac I ,yeH"
"?si ecalp siht erehw nwod worran I elihw em revoc ot tnaw syug uoY" .dias I ",yakO"
fo tnorf ni tuo drows sih gnidloh
.tikloot ym otno dleh I sa naf noitalucric eht ssim ot gniyrt ,dnuorg eht ot yldrawkwa deppord I  .kcab dellac eh
".morf degreme yllausu senihcam eht taht noitcerid eht ni klaw dna
.kcen reh dnuora ti gnilcric ylwols nageb dna
,moc.nozamA hguorht elbaliava
",moor eno taht ni kcab sralloc eht lla derebmemer I ,tnemngissa
.ti pota gniyal naf noitalucric nekorb a fo sniamer eht htiw
.trapa sretem derdnuh a
".ytilicaf siht ta regnol on
.noisserpxe ?gniod er'uoy kniht uoy od tahW
.deksa I "?si gniht taht
rehto eht dna uoy peek ot tnatropmi os
,hgis gib rehtonA
".syad neves ro xis rof neeb ylno evah dluow yaled ehT ?dam ehs sI"
.ot evah eW“  .dias I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
neht dna ,terpretni ot detrats aimaH "!on
nwoD arabmA ot kcab og ot deen tsuj eW"
,esac elgnis a tuo dellup dna sevlehs strap eht ot revo dedaeh ehS .sseug I cigol ym gniees
.raf os nuf neeb s'tI"
"?thgirla eb ot gniog s'ehs erus uoy erA"
,secnegilletni laicifitra enasni fo stolp eht gnitaefed ton
.sevlehs eht no strap eht erew ta dekool I gniht tsrif ehT
,ecno sregnif reh gniyalps
,roolf etercnoc htooms eht gnola gnidils gnidnes dna edis eht no hctiws noitavitca eht gnikcilf
.traeh ta yttik nabru
.ilA fo ffo ralloc desrucca taht gnitteg fo epoh ylno ruo si ytilicaf tahT
.pohs ym ni kcab dah ti naht ylthgirb erom hcum gniwolg
.rehtie stobor anihcaM xaP yna t'nerew ereht edis sulp eht no tub
",ralloc eht ot kcab
,yaD ecyoR yb ”drowS dna ecneliS“  fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht  saw sihT    .did yeht  nehw
,llaw eht morf yawa deldnurt sebut eht fo eno sa ,yldliw teef reh dekcik ehS
esion gnikcilc a saw raeh dluoc ew lla litnu
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.em pots ot tsirw ym gnibbarg
a htiw moor a dnuof dna thgir ym ot eno tsrif eht denepo I
,thgit tuhs saw ni emac ew erehw tfahs tnev eht dna rodirroc eht ot kcab rood ehT
noitartsurf gniworg s'ilA htiw dna
stoboronan gniniatnoc laiv rehtona dna
reggirt eht no dellup regnif reh sa
.lla ni derdnuh wef
",nwoD arabmA ta kcab pu ti derewop I nehw did eno rehto eht ekil tsuj ,langis a gnittimsnart si ralloc ruoy ,yakO"
.etaf rieht wonk I litnu deifsitas eb ton lliw I" .dias aimaH
desrucca taht fo reh dir ot yaw a dnif dna
.sretuen dna ,selamef ,selam
,llams erew erehT
,don trohs a evag ehS
.esle gnihtyna dnuof evah ot ton
,yltfos erom nehT ".lliw uoy sA"
"?noitpo gniniamer ylno ruo taht sI"
,reh deksa I "?yako uoY"
,swap reh pu dleh ehS
gninnur gnol sih ni ylimaf liatkraD eht fo sevil citnamor eht gnitacilpmoc si ecyoR
,tfahs noitalitneV  .reh deksa I
.ylnmelos deddon ehS .deksa I
tuoba sesac depahs ebuc ,etihw
".ffiks eht htiw yats nac uoY .ti dnif ot elba eb dluohs ehs dna
,nwoD arabmA ot kcab ti edam ew retal syad eerhT
.erutseg sselpleh
.ilA deksa I "?gniht eno tsuj ro
,ralloc reh htiw stnemevom s’ilA gnikcart eb ot dah IA s’ytilicaf eht ,saremac elbisiv tuohtiw nevE
.tobor eht fo tnorf ni roolf eht no dednal dna ffo decnuob tI
.enot lufreehc denmad emas taht ni
,smra ym ni deldarc stoob ym htiw tooferab llits gninnur ,deffuh I
,sroloc suoirav ni seriw detaoc citsalp htiw dellif sreward egarots
,etarg nepo eht erofeb gnippots ,ecap ruo denekciuq htob eW
.teef sih otno kcab flesmih gnihsup ,deton eh
ffo ti deppop ti ,krow ruoy dehsinif d'uoy ytilicaf eht decnivnoc d'I ecnO
.citamotua ylraen sevom eht ,meht ta gnikool
yrev os era ew tub
,sserP xoF deruomrA yb dehsilbup seirots trohs dah sah dna
ekil dekool yeht tahw gnirebmemer dnim reven
.gnittimsnart saw ralloc eht noitcerid eht dekcehc
.delworg eh "!wonk t'nod I"
,sretem derdnuh a ebyam deklaw dah eW
,efas dna edistuo lla erew ew nehW  .nepo ti gnimmaj
.srood gnidils erom htiw
,rosnes dnuos a ,seriw lareves
smra elcatnet elbatcarter ruof dna pot no tinu rosnes diovo na htiw epahs xob ralugnatcer a ni tliub
na tuo gnittel dna spil reh ot sregnif reh gnisserp
,tnempiuqe reporp htiw nruter neht dna
.reggij ylbissop I taht emarf eht ni tes rosnes cinortcele
yppah ,niaga ti desolc I
,detartsurf era uoy wonk I ,ilA"
,denialpxe I ,eralg reh tA "?woh rebmemer uoy oD
,reh fo tnorf ni esac nepo na saw ereht dehsinif d'ehs nehW
,mih ot revo deppets ilA
",won peels ot sehsiw ehS"
,deksa I dna ,ycavirp elttil a reh evig ot tib a kcab deppets eW ".sseug
,sesnefed s'anihcaM xaP htiw laed ot eraperp tsum aimaH dna eoJ ,dleh neeb ecno dah ilA erehw ytilicaf anihcaM xaP eht hcaorppa yeht sA  .anihcaM xaP
.sbmob ruoy dliub ot ereh ton s'ehS"
ro uoY" .dias aimaH ",ti ekil ton od I"
,meht fo nezod owt tsael ta eb ot dah erehT
.dewollof I dna aimaH dna
.meht ta nwod derats eh sa trid eht otni sworruf gnol gniggid ,swalc eot sih dexelf yug gib ehT
.ytpme saw gab gnipeels s'ilA
"!pluhw —oolrieh ...nalC"
"?ti ta seldeen evisolpxe ruoy fo eno erif tsuj uoy t'ndid yhW"
.dias I ",ffo ralloc denmad taht gnitteg ot esolc siht s'ehs nehw yllaicepse ,ytinrete na eb llew sa yam syad xiS
ni tluser yam anihcaM xaP egamad ot gnitpmettA"  .esac bmob
.desseug I ,fles regnuoy reh fo edirts eht gnihctam
# # # ".rehtaF ,uoy knahT"
.nekcirts dekool aimaH  .dias I
,tnev eht revo wap ym dleh I
",reh retfa og nac I"  .yrt ot
,nalc eht ni stluda eht lla
fo sretem flah a dna owt lla ,strohs sih rof tpecxe dekan ,pu doots eH
.su ediug ot noisiv thgin roirepus ym no gnidneped
.gninrom eht ni nwoD arabmA ot kcab trats dna
"?yako ,raelc lla eht llac uoy litnu tiaw dna talf pord ll'I gnitoohs strats gnihtyna fi ,kooL
,sbmob cinos diputs esoht gnikam
ni efink ym demmaj d'I fi deneppah evah dluow tahw enigami ot deirt dna ,ylluferac yrev
,rood eht ta derif ehs sa dnuorg eht ot talf deppord I
hctah eht tuo sdrawkcab gnicnad
,kaolc sih no dnuorg eht no ilA dial aimaH ,ffiks ot kcab tog ew nehW
”,65 - tixE tfeL ,riA leB“
”owT traP ,drowS dna ecneliS“
,maercs deggar a tuo tel ilA sa ria eht ni enozo dellems I neht
,ilA" .feiler dna yruf fo erutxim a ecaf sih
,tnev eht dnuof uoy erehw ot kcab knihT"
,thgir llA" .tuo ekam ot hguone ysae saw noisserpxe reh ni deilpmi
.dnuora dekool dna pu doots I  ".taerg ,hO"
I dna kcab rotceted langis ym evag ilA
,derepsihw eh ",esolc era ew
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
"?tcerroc ,nur noitcudorp tnecer tsom sti detelpmoc sah ytilicaf sihT"
.detsetorp eh "!gninethgirf
.dias I ",uoy rof ysae taht neeb sah reh gnisiar enigami t'nac I tub
eh sa tlih s'drows eht no pirg sih gnisol ,esirprus ni dias aimaH
,edisllih eht nwod dna pu gniohce snoisolpxe eht fo dnuos eht ,ti otni pilc elohw reh deitpme ehS
"?taht peek ot tnaw uoY"
"?fo erac nekat s'ti naem uoy od tahW"
,deggel-ssorc tas aimaH
".nepo ti ecrof eturb tsuj ot gnivah fo esac a eb yam tI .langis etomer
",gnireetnulov m'I ,gniksa ton er'uoY"
.dnuorg eht no tops ot drah neeb evah dluow ti taht hsurb dna sevael hguone htiw derevoc
"!tinu ecivres a ton ,xof a si ilA ,yeH"  .tey ti derif t'ndah ehs tub ,wap reh ni saw lotsip reH
,elddim eht ni saw I
,sediseB" .detsetorp I
,kciht werg seert eht sa em dniheb gniklaw saw aimaH nooS .dettimda eh
".ti tsap thgir klaw dluoc ew ,dnuorg eht no seldeen enip dna hsurb siht lla htiW" .dias aimaH ",tluciffiD"  .dias I
".sevisolpxe fo trohs ,ees nac I eno ylnO"
,su woleb sretem eerht
,tsehc reh ssorca dedlof smra reh dah ilA .ti dettops yeht retfa meht nioj ot eert eht fo tuo gnippoh
.redluohs sih gnikahs ,yltnegru dias I ",gnissim enog s'ilA !pu ekaw ,aimaH" .dnatsrednu t'ndid I egaugnal a ni noitseuq desufnoc ,yzzum a htiw ekowa eh dna ,dehctiwt srae s'aimaH .yltnegru tuo dellac I "?ilA ?ilA"
a ekil gnihtyna ees t'ndid I"
,roolf tserof eht gnirevoc seldeen enip eht otni liat revo daeh gnilbmut ,drawrof welf
.reniatnoc taht otni uoy pord ot ydaer gnitteg saw ti nehw
.hctah leets retem owt yb retem owt a yb thgit delaes ,llih eht fo elgna eht dehctam emarf rood etercnoc A
koot I .dnuora rotceted langis eht gnigniws ,dias I ",pu dloH"
,thgieh ym tuoba saw tI
.tsaf gnikniht ,yllufreehc pu dellac I
.elims dessarrabme na em gnivig ,noitamrifnoc ni deddon ehs dna ,deksa I
,ilA ot denrut aimaH
na gnola tserof eht otni ffiks eht dediug ylluferac dna daor niam eht ffo dellup
.reganeet a s'ehS"
"…tub ,egavlas eht evol d'I ,em eveileB" .dias I
"!nopaew a evah neve t'nod uoY"
"?ereh uoy dnuof aimaH erofeb gniog erew uoy noitcerid hcihw rebmemer t'nac uoY"
uoy oD" .duola deksa I
".od I sa ilA htiw dnob on evah uoy dna ,suoregnad oot raf s'tI
noitcerid etisoppo eht ni gniylf drows sih
,nwoD arabmA ot kcab og lliw eW
gnidliub stik uoy dah
ehs dna ,deppots gnihctiwt citnarf s'ilA
,htaerb peed a ni koot
.denrecnoc gnidnuos ,reh deksa aimaH
.anihcaM xaP ot tuo dellac I
,pu tas ,ffo tnew noisolpxe eht nehw I dna ilA htiw nellaf dah ohw ,aimaH  .ria eht ni gnisir
.noitartsurf ni dnah sih devaw eH ".tsav si
.deralced aimaH ",tnellecxE"
dehsinif erew yeht fI" .meht dlot I
,ilA rethguad xof detpoda sih dna
dna ffiksrevoh eht fo kcab eht morf xobloot ym debbarg I
,noziroh eht evoba gnikeep nus gninrom ylrae eht ,tserof eht gnilaever
pmuhw-pmuhw fo seires duol a saw erehT
.yalc gniledom yarg eb ot deraeppa tahw fo ebuc rellams a dnuof I retnec eht nI
era stinU ecivreS ehT"  "?ereh yeht erA"
.hgual gniwaffug a tuo tel mih edam hcihw
ta gnola delevart ew sA
esolc su thguorb yllanif ssaP reviR doolB fo tsew dna sniatnuom eht fo htuos levart 'syad erom owT  yaD ecyoR yb
.tnemeerga ni deddon ehs dna ,dias I
.gnihtyna draeh su fo rehtien tub
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,retemaid ni taht fo sdriht owt ebyam etarg latem a htiw
.lrans tnelis a ni kcab nward spil
,yltnatculer deddon ehs neht tub
,hsiloof eht tcetorp rotaerC"
,nwoD arabmA fo ytic espylacopa-tsop eht ni gnivil hcet scinortcele drapoel a ,eoJ ,enO traP ni ylsuoiverP  snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT dna
”drowS dna ecneliS“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.noitpo na reven saw tahT"
.derutseg dna pu dekool ilA
.yrgnuh pu ekow ehs fi ilA rof noitrop a edisa gnittes
"!on ,hO ?…ehs did erehW"
.reh ediseb dettauqs eh sa mih no gnisucof yllanif seye reh ,eciwt deknilb ilA .spil reh ot regnif gib eno gnisserp ,dias aimaH
.deb ograc s'ffiksrevoh eht ni ti tfel d'eh erehw morf drows sih debbarg eH .mih
.stsif otni denethgit sdnah
.noitalucric ria eht etipsed desusid dna ytsum dellems ria eht dna
yletanutrof osrot s’tobor eht sa ,moor eht ssorca
,reh tcetorp dluow I taht reh ot htao na erows I
.krad eht hguorht derad eh sa tsaf sa gnicap detrats eh sa mih gniwollof
.tinu anihcaM xaP a tsniaga doog hcum od dluow ti fi sa
"?uoy htiw ereh erew ynam woh rebmemer
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,erehwemos ecnartne na eb tsum erehT
.deraor aimaH "!ilA"  .denepo hctah eht tnemom eht ni gnihsur
.gnissim htob loot-itlum dna
.tnemhsinotsa ni deksa I
.deb ograc s'ffiks eht morf tik dia tsrif a debbarg I elihw
yrruf yb tluda na tey etiuq ton si ehs taht tegrof I semitemoS
.raer eht pu koot ilA dna
.erusserp gnisaeler enigne maets a ekil
aimaH rof thgit ylbissopmi saw ti tub ,tib a sredluohs ym hcnuh ot gnilliw saw I fi ,oot dluoc I
taht was dna nwod dekool I nehw ,dniheb eep ot eert ydnah a gnidnif no tnetni ,pu tog I .reddalb ym tsuj saw ti timda ot evah I tub
"?sklof ruoy ot emoh kcab reh ekat uoy t'ndid yhw oS"  ".sirbuh erup
lla ta ton saw I"
.sdnah rieht gnikahs dna pu gnidnats ,meht dlot I
.retnec eht ni swor owt ni tes sehcneb dna selbat leets gnol nezod-flah a htiw
,yranecrem nagazaw a ,aimaH yub derih saw
",segnih elbisiv ro eldnah on htiW"  .ilA morf kool
.tnadnudeR ot sutats s'693-256 gnitadpU .noitacifiralc eht rof uoy knahT .tcerroc si tahT"
",ylniatreC"  "?tuo em tel dna
.yllatnemirepxe ti no dekconk
",ksir ta uoy gnicalp fo aedi eht yojne t'nod I"
ygolohtna dlrow derahs eht ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw hcihw ,yaD ecyoR yb
,ria eht ni yletarepsed gnikcik teeF
si enola ti og dluoc yeht kniht ot enoemos roF
,lotsip reh derif ilA
ylpeed gnikool dna
na ekil gnihtyna
.ria eht ni reh gnidloh selcatnet eht hguorht gnicils ,cra ediw a ni drows sih gnuws eH
,rood tnorf eht wolb ot evisolpxe taht esu nac eW
",evisolpxe citsalp s'taht kniht I"
,yeboR nhoJ yb detide
,ralloc trihs reh denottubnu ilA
",kool ot noitcerid a su evag uoY" .ilA htiw
,elcatnet rehtona hguorht decils aimaH .em ediseb ylduol deltsihw ilA sa ,detuohs I
.mih rof dehcaer seno gniniamer eht sa
detelpmoc tsal ruoy ecnis syad 620,4 neeb sah tI" .srekaepsduol eht revo ylireehc dias anihcaM xaP "!693-256# tinU ecivreS ,sgniteerG"  .tuhs
.citnarf gnidnuos ,detuohs aimaH "!ilA"
.dnuora gnikool ,edisni deppets I
.srosnes dnuos fo noitcelloc eht saw suoiruc tsoM
!raelc er'ew ,aimaH" .detseretninu tsuj erew yeht ebyam ro
.roolf eht ta detniop saw ti hguoht ,swap reh ni lotsip reh ,nworf a ni tes saw ecaf s’ilA
.nwod rettis eht dloh ot sparts htiw
,nwod gnidils detrats I ".em
"?ekat anihcaM xaP did stik ynam woH"
.etalsnart ot hguone ysae saw ecaf reh no noitartsurf dna regna fo kool eht tub ,ognil erutseg reh wonk t'ndid I
".rab noitar a dna retaw uoy gnivig em ot elbaima erew uoy tuB
,railimaf kool siht fo yna seoD"
,ruoh na sretemolik net ylerab
,flesym tnerap a neeb reveN"
a aiv dellortnoc eb tsum tI
.noitartsurf ni rae reh dehctarcs neht ,secap ytfif tuoba ta deppots ehS
,htrae eht otni swalc eot sih gud
.nepo ebuc elttil eht deirp dna ,ilA morf kcab lootitlum ym koot I nehT
.dne eht ta ytilicaf eht otni repeed del rood egral
,ylfeirb ria eht otni gnitfil llih eht fo pot eritne eht
rotceted langis ym
reh hguoht ,elttil a gnilims llits ,deddon ehS
,kcab dellor moor eht fo tnorf eht ta rood ehT "!tfihs krow
,ecalp taht depacse I nehw saw eert
.llec rewop s'bmob eht dna pihc eht neewteb noitcennoc eht pins ot rettuc eriw  s'loot-itlum eht esu ot gnidnetni ,nwod dehcaer I ".ezeens
,reeb reh htiw aet yenoh fo spis gnidart
.retemillim a sa hcum sa egdub t'ndid rood denmad ehT
.niaga gniklat decitcarp ehs sa taorht reh esae ot
yeht did erehw nehT ?ytrihT"
",neht htob uoy ot kcul dooG"  ".raf
na m'I taht tcaf eht rof pu edam hcihw
"!uoy ediug rotaerC"  "!tib a ni
uoy eeS" .ni tnew I sa tik loot ym gnibbarg
.thgiew elbaredisnoc sih htiw eldnah eht no ni denael dna detnurg neht
.sllih eht dniheb deraeppasid nus eht ,eta ew sA
.ksa ot demees noisserpxe s'ilA ?tahW  .drah oot
,tnempiuqe thgir eht dnif dna
,swap reh htob pu dleh dna
rotnemrot ruoy tnorfnoc yam uoy taht os
,tekcop reh morf reilrae tliub d'ehs evisolpxe cinos eht dellup ehS  .deksa eh
,rotceted langis eht gnikcehc yllacidoirep
.stinu anihcaM xaP-non ot elbaliava ton si noitamrofni tahT"  .deksa I
.em ot suoivbo t’nsaw esoprup esohw
"?dekrow stik rehto eht dna uoy erehw siht sI"
,kcab dils hctah leets eht ,enihw ciluardyh a htiW "!yad ecin a evaH" .deilper anihcaM xaP
.mra reh otni detcejni eh hcihw fo htob
,meht deksa I "?tahw won oS"
"…syad erom wef A" .reh dlot aimaH
.yrotimrod eht ot kcab gnidael yawrood eht sdrawot denrut dna
,htaerb sih tuo welb aimaH
.snerraW peeD eht morf knuj pu gid ylefas ot woh em gnihcaet saw ehs nehw ,ecno em ot ti dewohs mom yM" .reh dlot I
,deerf eb tsum yeht ,evila llits era yeht fI
.tsewhtron eht sdrawot detniop I
.evisolpxe fo pmul eht ta gnimia
,smra sih ni ylthgit deldarc reh tpek eH
tog dna modnar ta ssel ro erom tfel eht ot denrut I
,sdoow eht hguorht yaw ruo gnikcip detrats eW  ".em gnidulcni
".ti nihtiw ylleurc os denosirpmi eb ot stik rehto rof
.gninepeed nworf sih ,dedda aimaH
,ti pota detnuom aremac a htiw elop gnitsur a dettops aimaH nehw
,aimaH ot gnihtemos dengis ehs dna ,pu dekriuq pil reh fo egde eht nehT
,etunim a rof thguoht ehS  .deksa I
reh sa ,yas ot demees ehs !gnitiaw erom oN
.tuo dellac I ",ilA"
,seires serutnevdA nexiV deR
dlo na yfirret ot thgir on dah uoY
tnegru na tuo tel rotceted eht sa ,hpmuirt ni detuohs I "!erehT
".ecruos langis eht fo pot no thgir er'ew kniht I"
.rallip eht delcric ehs sa daeh reh gnihctarcs
"!tiaw ,hO"  .xof llams a ro
?wenk yllaer ohw tub ,erofeb kcab morf metsys tropsnart emos ot noitadnuof eht neeb ylbaborp dah yehT
.em ot ti evag uoy fi sruoy fo drows gib taht pu kcip neve
",won reggib s'ehS"
?em wohs uoy naC .gniht eno ,yakO"
.elgna na ta pu dleh ,dnah etisoppo reh fo mlap eht ta lotsip reh gnitoohs gnimim
,tuo tohs wap s'ilA
",kaeps ot yrt t'noD"
,yltnatculer deddon ilA  ".teiuq stik
.lla ta evom t’ndid rood eht dna ,tneb ylerab drows ehT
,htob su rof rennid kooc dna erif a dliub
demmals neht hcihW
aimaH gnipleh no delttes I os
.ylfeirb dehcnilf I
.swalc ym gnixelf ,skcos dna stoob ym ffo gnillup detrats I ".weiv lairea na deen tsuj eW ?oS"
a em evag dna deknilb ilA ,em ediseB
.niarts ot deunitnoc eh sa ,deksa I
,rotceted eht ilA eviG" .dias eh
.nepo llits saw ytilicaf eht otni repeed gnidael rood eht tub
su dah ti sgniht eht rof slairetam noitcurtsnoc dna doof erehw
ekoms dna tsud ,flesti no ni despalloc ytilicaf eht fo sniamer eht sa
.spihc lortnoc llams dna
",oga emit gnol yrev a saw tI"
.tas ecno evah tsum selcihev
,egavlas ni mosnar s'gnik a ta ecnahc ym tsol d'I
,yldetaeper pam sih dekcehc aimaH
.terger peed htiw dellif saw ti ekil gnidnuos eno siht
dna tik loot ym gnibbarg ,deerga I
.stik esoht dnif d'yeht gnileef eht dah I
,daeh reh ot talf srae
.ekawa gniknilb ,dias eh "?tahw —ahW"
revoc tnev a nepo deirp dna
,ylnmelos dnuora dekool ilA  "?rebmemer uoy oD
",rood kciht a s'tahT"
,IA enasni eht yb kcen reh dnuora dekcol
,rood eht tuo em htiw gninnur dna gnihguoc ,teef reh ot deppord ehS
,ilA '–olpxe evah I'"
,tniop eht eugra ot detnaw ilA ekil dekool ti
"?won od ew od tahW"
a revo tib a saw tfahs tnev ehT
sa eb t'ndluohs tceffe llarevo eht ,xis saw ehs nehw sa htgnerts emas eht ta saw egrahcsid s'ralloc eht fI" .dias I
"?ilA ,neht drazil gib siht gniwollof peek
,od ot em geb yam ehs tahw daerd I“
.ylsuoicsnocnu ralloc reh hcuot ot pu dehcaer wap reh sa ,ediw tnew seye reh dna kcab deppilf srae s'ilA  ".seceip ynit otni ffiksrevoh ruoy ro pohs ym rehtie wolb ot hguone eb dluow ebuc elttil tahT .sbmob detavitca-dnuos
?em raeh uoy naC !ilA"
s'eh nehW .tenalpruF hguorht elbaliava dna
tuohtiw tsomla strap eht gnilbmessa ,ylkciuq dekrow ehS .sloot llams dna strap rehto dna
"?yawyna ,tuo teg uoy did woH"
.stekcos rieht fo tuo eglub ot nageb seye s'ilA sa ,detats ti
ecaps deddap a laever ot pu gninepo
.erom ecno tobor eht ta derif ilA
nwod ti gnittup ,dias I ",hO"
!PMURC gninefaed a gnidne
,drawrof retemolik a tuoba yaw ruo krow ot ruoh na tsomla su koot tI
ebyam roolf a no tam rebbur kcalb a gniees ylno ,gninepo eht otni nwod dekool I sa gninetsil ,eciwt eman reh dellac I
"?fo tuo edam drows taht s'tahW"
"?ni teg ot yaw tseb eht siht si tuB" .dias I
.kcen reh dnuora morf elcatnet pmil won eht elgnatnu reh depleh I sa gnihguoc ,pu tas ehS
.llew sa gnituohs deirt dna gninepo eht ni daeh ym kcuts I
,dnah ni drows ,drazil eulb dekan flah ,suoiruf ylsuoethgir fo sretem flah a dna owt dna
,drawnwod derif ehs nehT
,deksa dna flesym fo dloh a tog I
.dias yllanif I ",yrros m'I"
.wollaws ot reh rof tluciffid gnimoceb ydaerla s’tI
,htuos eht sdrawot gnidaeh
,ralloc reh ot rotceted eht pu thguorb I
,rood nepo rehtona hguorht tnew eW  ".stinu
.emarf rood eht dna ti neewteb walc a tif ylerab dluoc I thgit os saw rood eht no laes eht ,lleH .trohs pu emac I ,fo kniht dluoc I snaem yreve yb gnihcraes fo ruoh flah a tsomla retfA
.pihc lortnoc eht ot seriw fo riap a yb detcennoc ,ediw sretemitnec owt ebyam ,esac leets rellams a saw ti fo retnec eht nI
",segelivirp negyxo fo noitacover eht
.peels ot denethgirf oot tub ,detsuahxe
rof gnikool ,hctah eht fo smaes eht gnola ti denihs I
.ecalp ni rosnes dnuos dna pihc lortnoc ,gniriw
.rotceted langis eht tuo dellup
,eerht-ytnewt dehcaer eh nehW
.ti gnitargetnisid
,thginrevo ereh pmac lliw eW" .em dlot eh
.htiw yalp dna nepo pop dluoc I lenap lortnoc a neve toN"
.yaw eht fo tuo degdod I dna ilA htob sa
.srallip eht tuo gnitnuoc
,ngis on saw ereht ilA fO
?siht gniod ehs si yhW"
,flesym rof kcits a debbarg I
.swap reh morf nug eldeen eht dellup eh sa
.nees d'I smoor mrod eht ni sdeb fo rebmun eht gnihctam
.tcatnoc edam yeht sa gnidolpxe strad eht
retarc ralugerri na gnimrof
.ecap sih hctam ot sruof lla no nwod og dna meht pmud ot ydaer tsomla
.seldeen evisolpxE ”!mooB“
,yawa dekcab dna dewollaws I
.ytilicaf eht ot ecnartne eht eb ot dah tahw ot
meht pleh ot ecnahc a evah d'I depoh I
,dehgis ilA  "?dnatsrednu uoy oD
.s'ilA ekil sralloc htiw dellif
.seye ruo gniteem ton
,taht retfa yas ot gnihtyna fo kniht yllaer t'ndluoc I
,gnikaeps morf reh stneverp taht ralloc a evomer pleh ot
ilA noitcerid s'aimaH ta dna
yrros ylpeed ma I"
,tliub d'ehs ebuc eht dna ,sevisolpxe eht fo lufdnah elbuod a debbarg ehS
,ylfeirb aimaH ot derutseg dna deddon ehs nehT .yraew gnikool
",anihcaM xaP yb renosirp dleh gnieb stik ytriht erew erehT"
",ti htrow saw ti ,yrrow t'noD"
,enilas ni dednepsus seirujni lanretni riaper ot demmargorp
"!taht ekil drazil
",gnorw ton era …uoY"
,elcric a ni denrut ehS  .deksa aimaH "?ilA
.nepo gnirettulf seye reh
,nwod kcab gnippord erofeb
,stik rof dezis riahc deddap
.but reniatnoc eht hguorht gnihsams drows sih ,niaga deraor aimaH sa
eveileb I"  .edisllih peets a fo egde eht ta
"!enod yllufrednoW
,lotsip reh tuo dellup ilA
.derepsihw ehs ",ton yhW"
.dengis dna dehtuom ehs ?woH
s'aimaH ni gnispalloc erofeb
yb enod si taht gnihtemos si tI"
"!smsinahcem
.su fo daeha thgil eht dettops ew nehw ,dednuofnu devorp ,ssenkrad eht ni etarg tnev eht ssap
,swalc ym rof erutxet elbabbarg ,hguor a dah krab rieht tub ,sknurt tsekciht eht evah t'nod senip burcS
"?taht teg reve uoy did woH"
.dias aimaH ",ton raef I"
.ereh fo tuo teg ot deen ew tub ,revetahw yakO" .deksa I
?yllaer ,hO gnirehtiw a em denrae hcihw ,deton I
.tinu rosnes s'tobor eht ffo degnip eldeen leets a dna
,tik a tisoped ot hguone gib
.kcen reh ot gnitniop ,dias I
.niaga lotsip reh gniretslohnu ,deddon ilA .mih
.esac ni tsuj ,hctah eht fo segde eerht rehto eht ta niaga deirt dna drows sih debbarg aimaH
"?thgirla eb ot gniog ehs sI"
.ylisae ti nwod dils dah ylbaborp ilA dna ,ediw retem flah
"?rood eht ta tohs uoy nehw pu meht desu uoY"
"!hcet fo eceip
",oot derugif I tahw s'taht ,haeY"
erehw roolf eht no skram eht yb gnigduj ,aera gnidaol ro egarag a ylbissop hguorht
.meht ot nwod dellac I "!thgir ruoy oT"
.woleb morf drawpu gniruop thgil
a dna ,strap dna tnempiuqe htiw denil erew sllaw ehT
,hcaer ot elbanu demees selcatnet eht ,rood eht tsaP
.etalptsehc deromra sih no stsif reh taeb neht ,dehtuom ehs !oN
,hsurb dekcinap a ni
",uoy htiw eerga attog I"
dna enip burcs yltsom
.smlap sih gnixelf ,roolf tserof eht no tas aimaH sa ,noitarepsed htiw ediw seye reh ,yldipar derutseg ilA
dah sevlehs rehtO
.ssenkrad sselnoom eht ni reh gniees ton ,etispmac eht dnuora dekool I
,thgin eht fo elddim eht ni em ekow taht sesnes denut-enif ylbidercni ym saw ti yas ot ekil d'I # # # .deirrow
,pu dehcaer ilA  "?eeS"
.mra reh fo koorc eht ni ti deldarc dna esac eht pu dekcip ehs nehT
,ilA ,uoy dnuof I erehw si sihT"
,drawrof spets ruof
".reh dellik ylraen taht dna ,dlihc llams a saw ehs nehw ,erofeb ecno deneppah ylno sah sihT" .yllacidomsaps gnihctiwt llits ydob reh
,egde dnah thgir eht gnola laes eht otni pit eht devohs eh sa yaw eht fo tuo deppoh I
eht deppord ehs sa dnuorg eht ffo ylidob reh gnitfil dna kcen s'ilA dnuora gnipparw ,tuo tohs mra tnorf s'tobor ehT
.ni dellor tobor deleehw-xis a dna
.tuo nug eldeen reh htiw ilA ,wap ym ni sebuc evisolpxe eht fo eno htiw em
.ria eht otni reh gniluah dna ,kcen dna sredluohs eht yb ilA gnibbarg ,gniliec eht morf dedlofnu selcatnet ecivres eerhT ".tnadnudeR
.revoc leets eht ta nwod derats ehs sa mirg gnikool
,yrgna os uoy edam I taht
,kcab dedlof srae
.lotsip eldeen reh tuo dellup ilA sa yaw eht fo tuo degdod
.noitartsurf ni daeh ym fo pot eht debbur I .dias I
",ereH"  .pots ot ilA dlot eh
.su morf yawa edis reh no gninrut erofeb
.deterpretni aimaH sa dengis ehs ,yako s'tI  ".ilA ,hguoht
".nihtiw stinu anihcaM xaP eht elbasid
.uoy fo taht ksa tonnac I …I"
".evitca llits si ecalp eht gnimussa
.rekihhctih flowerew
.rood eht hguorht peerc ot nageb ylwols ew dna
",tfahs tnev a rof kool s'tel os ,yakO"
ti fi ,erom yna sworg ehs fI
"?latem lluh s'ytic a tuo edam drows A"
,dnuorg eht no nepo tikloot ym saw dnif did I tahw ,esroW
,sgniht lareves gnidliub uoy evah yeht diD"
,tfahs eht fo sedis eht ot desserp stoob
.yawa sretem neves tuobA"
,srekaepsduol eht revo derewsna anihcaM xaP ",tnemngissa krow tnerruc rieht detelpmoc dah yeht ecno ,egarots mret gnol ni decalp erew stinU ecivreS llA"  "?og