",sseug nac I ,haeY"
,gnirewsna fo daetsnI
.deggurhs eh sa gniknalc romra sih
.yawa hguone raf nettog d'ew ekil leef t'ndid llits tI
.ydob sti ni sekips latem eerht gnivah etipsed ,gniog tpek tsuj gniht denmad ehT
nwod delian ton gnihtyreve tnaem hcihw
.rednetrab eht morf kool ytrid a gninrae
"?pu tup nac I gnihtemos ro tnet a evah uoy oD"
.reh dlot eh ",suoregnad oot raf ,suoregnad ooT"
.tfarc eht tolip lliw ilA"
sgniggel kcalb revo triks kcalb a erow ehS
",pohs ym fo tuo teG"  .ralloc A
,yprihc a ni decnuonna dna
,retal sdnoces fo elpuoc a htrae eht ot hsarc ti draeh I
.reh ffo gniht denmad eht teg dluoc ew ecalp siht dnuof ew nehw taht depoh yllaer I
",deipucco llew tpek ma I"
,ni deklaw I nehw egats eht no erew sregit fo oirt A
.enim naht reggib tol a erew taht lufhtuom elohw a
.gnilims dna pu srae reh ,serutseg emos edam
",gnivrats dna dekan
,reh dnuof I nehw
.yad a flah ylraen rof elbisnesni saw ehs drah os reh dekcohs ralloc live taht ,em dlot ehs nehW .saw
daor edart nrehtron eht otno tuo dellup ew sa ilA ta revo decnalg I
.kcab gnidlof srae sih ,reh ta deugra aimaH
".tnemhsilbatse ruoy ot emoc evah ew nosaer eht si ehS"
".ton od ylniatrec I
,deripxe mitciv sti nehw nwod tuhs ti spahrep ro ,rewop fo tuo nar tsuj ti spahreP
.dleh saw ehs erehw ecalp siht dnif uoy yaS"
dna seye ym desolc I
neeb dah taht tnemirepxe namuh dlo emos ro ecar gnirrucco yllarutan a erew yeht fi erus t'nsaw I
yas ot gniog ton m'I .snerraW
ffo gnippans sehcnarb
,edart rof erehwesle ro sorypmE hgiH morf nwod thguorb sffits tcejorP noitamalceR eht raeg eht fo emos ekil wen rof lles t'ndluow tI
ot srelevart ynam teg ton od eW
.ecno ralloc eht deppat I ".em yap nac uoy ,tuo ti erugif nac I fI .stluser eht uoy evig ot gnineve worromot ylflesmaD eht ta uoy teem ll'I dna ,gniht siht enimaxe ot yad a em evig ,kooL" .mih dlot I
nar eh ,mih ta sregnif reh evaw dna eralg ot deunitnoc ehs sA
.taorht reh revo deretnec thgil der gniwolg ylmid a htiw
".htiw deniagrab eb nac anihcaM xaP semitemos taht dlot neeb evah I"
.pu gnithgil yalpsid sti
"…ot ecnahc a teg t'ndid I dna em detpurretni eh tuB
…ot naem ton did I oN"
eltsihw gnicreip A
;seohs htiw rehtob t'ndid ,noinapmoc reh ekil ,dna
".ralloc evals a s'tI"
.htiw railimaf saw I esle erehwyna morf ron
.ereht tniop a dah eh ,yakO
.gniog dah yeht ssenisub revetahw
.nexiv eht ot gnivaw ,deksa I
,devirra ilA dna aimaH retal ruoh-flah a tuobA
.dneirf ym ,laed A"
.seye yllanoisacco ro ,sbmil ynam oot ebyam htiw sklof
.sdradnats esoht yb neve  driew erew owt esehT
morf tuo dessap saw I em dnuof aimaH emit eht yB
.denepo dah ti wohemoS
.hcaer reh fo tuo saw I litnu reh gniyt-goh ro
,god.ecioveht ta
"?ton ro reh rof doog s'tahw gnidiced uoy era rO .klat ydal eht teL" .dias I ",yeH"
neht dna ,em ta denworf aimaH
.walc eno htiw sih fo drows suomrone taht fo tlih eht deppat dna pu dehcaer eH
,reh rof detalsnart
,liat gnol retem owt ,kciht
".scinortcele swonk ohw enoemos htiw
.drows sih fo tlih eht barg ot kcab gnihcaer dnah eno
,nogard cihpromoporhtna na ekil erom
,kciht eno dna ediw sretemitnec eerht
gninnur gnol sih ni
.yldipar gnirutseg detrats dna aimaH ot denrut ehs neht
.denrecnoc gnikool ,dnah evissam eno ni redluohs reh pirg ot elbat eht ssorca dehcaer aimaH .stsif otni sregnif reh werd dna seye reh desolc neht tub ,gnihtemos derutseg ilA
"?xis saw ehs ecnis reh htiw taht gniod neeb ev'uoY"
# # # "!hcum yrrac nac I ekas s'ilA roF
".msinahcem eht gnilbasid
".kaew eht nopu yerp ohw elpoep fo sdaeh eht gnikaerb
.don prahs a evag dna
.yawa llor ot detrats ti nehw niaga ti gnibbarg neht
.kao egral ylralucitrap a fo esab eht yb gnihtemos ta gnikool ilA dna aimaH gnittops yllanif
"?ereh yats ot efas ti sI" .dias I
.yawyna ffuts taht droffa t'ndluoc doohrobhgien ym dnuora sklof tub
.reh dlot I ",gnihtyna tuo dnif t'ndid I naem t'nseod tahT .nepo
.wollof ot denrut ew sa denialpxe aimaH
"!segelivirp negyxo fo !tzrb —nimret ni tluser yam stinu —824 RORRE —ihcaM xaP gnigamaD !tzrB"
.hguoht thgir saw yug gib eht ,yltsenoH
seert fo espoc ybraen a rednu morf doow daed derehtag ilA elihw ,doof devreserp fo sretsinac delaes
,reh stespu syawla tsomla tI"
,ecalp a ni saw I
.deggurhs eH  .deksa I
.thguoht I ,pu werht ehs litnu elggig reh ekam tsuj ebyam rO  ".lataf
,ekahs ot em rof dnah sih dereffo neht
"?pleh ot od I nac tahw ,yeH"
gnittes tsuj saw nus ehT
",em rof yrrac nac uoy taht
"?reh detnaw eno oN"
.sdrow eht htiw yltnelis gnola gnihtuom saw ehs ees ot
,gniraelc ybraen a otni daor eht ffo ffiks eht dellup ilA emit eht yb
,nik yna rof gnihcraes fo sraey owt retfA
htron denrut ew sa ,nwoD arabmA fo klub derevoc-eniv taerg eht dednuorrus taht sgnidliub rehtegot-delbboc eht dnuora delcric eW .hpk ytriht
,hsarc a htiw su morf yawa revo delppot neht ,ylduol gnikaerc
nwoD arabmA ni noitatuper a evah uoY"
.ssenkrad eht otni deraeppasid dna seert fo espoc eht sdrawot nar eh sa ,redluohs sih revo kcab dellac eh
,gnitsetorp yltnatsid
namuh remialC‘-non lanoisacco eht dna seirruf fo wolf tnatsnoc a
,redluohs reh hcuot ot tuo dehcaer I
,etispmac ruo fo retemirep eht gnicap ,ffo devom neht
.kniht I dnuorgrednu peeD .yks latem dna sllaw latem fo ecalp enihcam a
taht pu kcip ehs did erehW"
".uoy pleh dluow taht ,dekoolrevo evah thgim uoy gnihtemos dnif thgim I tuB .si eno on
".sevlesmeht naht rellams si taht lla fo rotcetorp a si thginK ggE nA" .enim naht
,hgual gniraor a tuo tel aimaH  .mih dlot I
,erow ehs esuolb der dekcen hgih eht fo ralloc eht otni gniraeppasid ruf kcen etihw ,tlep odexut llabddo ylthgils
,deksa I "?kcuf ehT"
pleh ot em gnitcepxe pohs ym otni emac uoY"
.ralloc reh fo kcab eht ees dluoc I os daeh reh gnirewol dna retnuoc eht ot resolc gnippets
.tsev kcalb a denottub saw hcihw revo
,stnaig eulb erew yeht taht noitnem ot derehtob reve dah ydoboN
.xof rellams hcum a doots mih ot txeN
"?cisum emos yalp I fi dniM"
,drapoel a rof egareva naht retrohs m'I dna
ot ralloc a esu dluoc uoy yllaciteroehT
".ecnis em ot duola drow a dias t'nsah ehS
ti gnilbmur dna peed os eciov sih ,deksa saw-eh-revetahw eulb gib eht
.ralloc s'ilA slortnoc taht gniht eht kaerb I litnu
,did I nehW .tohs a htrow saw rewop emos ti gnivig thguoht I os ,secafrus rieht no citats tneibma
.rekihhctih flowerew
.sehcaorkcoc deppot talf ,kcalb ekil gnikool ,tuo dehcram senihcam llams fo enil a ,kao eht fo esab eht ta eloh dezis-esuom a morF  .mrala eht dnuos ilA edam dah tahw was neht ,detniuqs I .eert ralucitrap a fo esab eht ot detniop eH .dias aimaH
.ylpeed gnihgis dna sdnah sih ni ecaf sih gnittup erofeb ,tnemom a rof tnelis saw eh nehT .detrats aimaH "…reh rof tuo gnihctaw tsuj ma I"
.mirg ecaf reh ,deddon ilA .deksa I
"?ma'am ,dexif deen uoy od tahW"
,mraw saw yad ehT  .yrotirret yrruf
dna stop gnikooc
.noitcerid yreve ni
",won rof yenom ruoy peeK"
"?evals ruoy ton s'ehS"
noitpmussa emas eht ekam lla yeht taht tsuj si tI"
.raeh tonnac ohw esoht htiw etacinummoc ot ti fo tib a swonk enoyrevE
eht fI .efink ytilitu egral a dna lotsip eldeen deretsloh a dedulcni hcihw ,tsiaw reh dnuora tleb tnempiuqe
"?tnemhsilbatse siht fo roteirporp eht
.yawrood eht rednu dekcud eh sa ecalp eht dnuora derettacs snamuh remialC‘ eht morf serats wef a gnitteg remrof eht
ygolohtna dlrow derahs eht ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw hcihw ,yaD ecyoR yb
,esle gnihtemos morf tuc sbals etisopmoc morf rehtegot delbboc neeb dah ti ekil dekool romra siH
,repeekpohs a er'uoY
",tinu anihcaM xaP a retnuocne ew emit yreve sneppah tahT"
.nepo ti draeh I sa delgnij rood pohs ym evoba detnuom slleb fo gnirts ehT
,delims eH          .deksa I
,detalsnart aimaH dna derutseg neht ehS
",pu dloh ,tiaW"  ".emit yreve
,nihc ym htiw level daeh reh fo pot eht
.me' htiw enod erew stsitneics eht nehw ytic gnitaolf a fo edis eht revo depmud
.tluciffid gniwollaws gnikam ylbaborp dna ,taorht reh gnisserpmoc ylbisiv ,kcen reh dnuora saw gniht lufwa eht thgit woh ees dluoc I pu esolC
,deilper aimaH ",krow yranecreM"  "?seitilicaf anihcaM xaP nwod gnitnuh ton er'uoy nehw od syug uoy od tahw oS"
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
,elpmis os erew ksat eht taht dluoW"
.niaga gnikrow ti teg ot CLT elttil a dedeen tsuj taht hcet ssim ot semitemos ysae saw ti ,nwoD arabmA fo slewob eht morf yad yreve pu gud gnieb parc hcum os htiW
".skrow ti woh etiuq wonk reven uoy hcet anihcaM xaP htiw ,niaga nehT .smaes eht ees t'nac uoy gnorts os si nioj
.deddon I dna ,laem eht retfa sehsid eht gnihsaw demim ilA
,retaw dna doof reh evag I .ecalp lufwa taht epacse ot yaw a dnuof d’ehS“
decnalg neht ,erutseg ot em ot denrut ilA  "?tahw sehsiW"
.hcum oot nialpmoc t'ndluohs rednetrab eht dediced dna ,roolf ecnad s'rab eht dnuora gnilbmuts sdnah sih ni drows a htiw tnaig knurd a enigami
,niaga ralloc reh edih ot thgit pu denottub trihs reh fo kcen eht ,nexiv ehT
.daeh taerg sih koohs eH
,sserP xoF deruomrA yb dehsilbup seirots trohs dah sah dna
.yawa saw I elihw pohs ym revo hctaw ot draug eht ni wenk I dneirf a rof egnarra dna rehtegot raeg ym teg ot yad a koot ylno tI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sloop gge eht ot dees rieht reffo
aimaH dna ,enim no desucof seye reh ,niaga derutseg ilA
.nwod ssalg ym tes dna reeb ym ffo dehsinif I ".taht
.su rehtob ot efildliw elitsoh yna t’nsaw ereht erus gnikam ylbaborp
.htron tnatsid eht ni sniatnuom eht tsap stresed eht ni gnivil ,dlot neeb d'I os ro ,sdrazil fo hcnub
"—cafsitas evah lliw I !os ronoh ym yllus ton lliw uoY"
.evissergga ylerar era taht ekil stinu noitcurtsnoC .ylbaborP"
,erif eht fo tnorf ni llab elbaresim a ni nwod tas
eht tub ,teg t'ndid I snrettap ni gnivom sregnif dna swap
.tob eht tih yeht sa ria eht hguorht gnikcarc seldeen ynit eht
dluoc I .doog ytterp si noisiv thgin yM" ,dias I daetsnI
".hcet xaP nevig ereht esirprus on
.ddo elttil a saw semitemos ti fi neve ,cisum doog dah syawla ylflesmaD ehT # # # .sloot ym tuo dellup dna
.llew sa ilA erujni yllataf ylekil dluow ti kaerb ot hguone taerg taeh ro ecrof ynA .romra ym sa drah sa si latem ehT
!deifitnedi 693-256# tinU ecivreS" ,enot lufreehc
hcihw ,tnemeerga ni deggurhs aimaH .mih dlot I
,roolf eht no gnittis tsuj yb melborp ralimis sih devlos aimaH .enim htiw level saw daeh reh os taes hgih a htiw riahc a debbarg ilA
rewol eht ni gnittimsnart dna evila eb thgim
.sralloc eht lla lortnoc ot metsys noitanidrooc lartnec
.redluohs ym revo gnuls llayrrac a ni
.esneffo kcom ni gninworf ,traeh sih revo dnah a decalp drazil gib ehT
.tnetni seye nedlog reh ,em ta pu dekool ilA
.ereht seirruf rehto erew erehT
,delevart I sa gnola reh thguorb I oS
na raew did ehs
fo raelc llew peek ot denrael evah elpoep yM"
aiv degrahcer eb nac hcet NDNG emoS"
.tenalpruF hguorht elbaliava dna
fo dnik emos dah ni saw ilA ytilicaf revetahw ylbaborP"  .meht dlot I
.flah a dna retem a tsuj ta
"?ereh dneirf ruoy si ohw dnA"
.kcen ym ni kcirc a teg em gnikam saw ohw yug eht saw tsrif ehT
".nagazaW a ma I" .ecnetnes lamron yltcefrep a erew taht fi sa ,dias eh
ton er'uoY" .denworf I
.em ot teg ot detrats gnignis stekcirc eht rof tpecxe dnuos fo kcal deunitnoc eht sa
,edoc NDNG a saw ereht debircsnI
,yas ot detrats dna pu dekool I ,tup yats ot gniog saw pmoc eht erus saw I ecnO
.hcuot thgil a htiw sdiks sti no ti gnippord
,degreme ediw sretemitnec net dna gnol retem flah a tuoba rednilyc revlis
".noitseuq tnavelerri na yllausu si 'yhW'“ .deilper aimaH
,retaw fo rehctip a tog eh elihw
.ria eht hguorht welf sretnilps sa em dna ilA dleihs ot kaolc sih fo egde eht gnibbarg aimaH ,kcab pets a koot lla eW
.ilA no sucof ot gnitator
a saw ehs fi rednow em gnikam ,yug gib eht htiw noitasrevnoc ym gnirud teiuq gnipeek neeb d'ehS
.ilA ,yrros m'I"
saw tI .tnioj nepo eht ta gnitniuqs ,pu eceip eno dleh I
.llams dna detalosi
,ecalp eht fo tuo egavlas nac I raeg NDNG revetahw dna
"?reh ffo ti ekat ot ereht od nac uoy kniht uoy od tahW
.dehsilop dekool sedis eht enif os tuc ,erauqs retemitnec a tuoba doow fo ebuc a saw meht fo hcae potA
.nagazaW eht deksa I
.tnetni secaf rieht ,reh htiw serutseg gnignahcxe
".rehtegotla gniht rehtona si anihcaM
.dekrow ew elihw tnelis yletulosba yats ot dah ew taht ylnO .yhw wenk eno oN
.tleb ym morf gnignah loot tekcop a dna ,swalc ym ,sgnaf ym dnoyeb nopaew a evah t'ndid I
eman reh tahw reh deksa I neht dna
.noisiced tnelis a gnihcaer wohemos ,tnemom a rof rehto hcae ta dekool xof dna nagazaW ehT  "?laed riaF .emit ym gnitsaw rof ecirp eht sa
pu yaw eht lla doots eh fi desseug I dna ,pohs ym fo elddim eht ni doots eh sa teef dewalc taerg no revo dehcnuh eH
,sgnaf sih ta kool a teg did I emit sihT
.sretem flah a dna owt
,siht dnuof ew oga shtnom owT .seY"  ".wohemos
,yldipar mih ta gnirutseg nageb ehS
,pmac ruo ot kcab gnihcram detrats dna retsloh sti otni kcab lotsip reh devohs ilA sa
siht otno dloh ll'I ,t'nac I fI"
"!demra ton osla er'uoY"
yaD ecyoR yb ”enO traP
.ssenkrad eht otni deraeppasid dna ria eht otni pu welf tobor ehT .pit sti htiw rednilyc eht gnihctac ,cra wol a ni
,deilper eh ",kcab eht nI"
",em evig ot tuoba er'uoy noitanalpxe tihsllub fo dnik tahw kcuf gniylf evig t'nod I"
.yleneres deilper eh
fo snaem a eb tsum ereht tub
",eltbus yltcaxe toN"
.liart ym dewollof dna yawa nur d'ehs taht dnuof I tfel I retfa syad owt tuB .ytluciffid
.esirprus ni dehsal liat yM
.dehsinif dah yeht ecno ,dias aimaH ",laed a evah uoY"
,ksa ot derutnev I ,top eht derrits nagazaW eht elihW
".ralloc denmad taht dnuora teg ot yaw tnaillirb a s'tI ?esu owt uoy egaugnal erutseg
"!mih ot ssenhsiloof ruoy kaeps ton lliw I"
,daeh sih koohs eH ".hcaer
,ytivitca anihcaM xaP
.meht htiw eltneg eb rotaerC
.nageb nagazaW eht "—lpxe ot tnemom a em wollA" .delworg I
.ecalp enihcam eht erofeb saw tahw rebmemer dluoc su fo enoN .deppandik
,demlehwrevo gnieb er'ew ekil sdnuos ti fI .eoJ ,ni teG"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,seirotirret yrruf ni ees yllamron t'nod uoy snrettap dna sroloc ni stlep htiw skloF
".snosaer suoivbo rof
.mih dniheb htrof dna kcab gnigniws diarb sih
elzzum ym dehcnip
.regdab gnuoy a ecno saw denimreted ew taht senob fo elip a ni saw tI"
.seenk reh neewteb deirub ecaf reh
.gnieb-llew s'ilA htiw denrecnoc erom saw I dna
yeht erA"  .gnihtemos
.deggurhs aimaH  .deton I
.regna htiw ffits liat dna sredluohs
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
".nac uoy sa ylkciuq sa yawa teg ot yrt
.ffiks eht ta devaw eH "!gnimoc m'I"
.erusopmoc reh deniager ehs sa erom ecno gnitalsnart
a dna selop munimula fo tes a yb decalper dna ffo nrot ecnis gnol pot latem etisopmoc eht ,ffiksrevoh pu-taeb a ediseb em rof gnitiaw erew riap ehT
.yllautneve ylflesmaD eht ot semoc ydobyrevE
,rellevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,dias aimaH dna ,deddon dna em ot kcab denrut ilA
.detsetorp I "!drawoc on m'I ,yeH"
,sgel reh dnuora depparw smra
".reh hcaet ot hguone ysae saw tI
,drawtuo gnidnapxe reve saw ytic ehT .elgnuj eht sdrawot
taht hcet yarts rof hcraes ot syad egavlas regnuoy ym ni desu ,gab ym morf tinu rotceted langis ym dellup I ".siht dnuof I
.desseug I "?ebyam citengaM"
ti kcarc t'ndluoc I dias tsuj I !yeh ,yeH"
.flesym rof elbat a dnuof dna
,gnineppah saw tahw ees ot deniarts I
eht woh nialpxe thgim tI"
,detuohs eh sa tuo sih fo drows eguh taht gniward ,teef sih ot depael aimaH
",gnikrow hcet elbisneherpmocni
.em ot revo neht ,mih ta dnah a gnivaw ,aimaH ta
"?meht wollof ew dluohS"
esaeler ot snaem a dniF
,noitnetta rof gnipeeb detrats ti ,seceip ralloc eht ot esolc rotceted eht thguorb I nehW .snerraW
"?kcen ruoy dnuora gniht taht s'tahW .ma'am ,yrroS"
.desaelpsid gnikool ,tsehc deromra sih revo smra sih dlof ot saw esnopser ylno s'nagazaW eht dna ,ruf ecaf reh kaos ot gnitrats sraet ,su neewteb yltnegru erom htrof dna kcab devaw ilA  "!taerg oot eb dluow uoy ot ksir ehT"
,tcejorP noitamalceR eht yb ecalupop yrruF eht ot tfig suoreneg a(
.reh gnikohc-flah s’ti ekil skool tI
,yaws ot nageb eert kao ehT
a knurt dewolloh eht morF
ro dlo teg ot woh gniwonk rof
,rednilyc eht fo pot eht morf tuo dekop sdne eht no sesnel aremac htiw eannetna fo riap A .sgel latem yldnips ruof no gniklaw
.gniht eht fo tser eht sa sselerutaef dna talf sa
,thguoht ni deworran seye s'ilA
,nees reve d'I yrruf rehto on ekil saw eH
,gnitalsnart aimaH htiw flesreh rof tnip-flah a deredro
.reh ecaf ot denrut I
".reh ot snoitseuq ruoy sserddA
,secnegilletni laicifitra enasni fo stolp eht gnitaefed ton s'eh nehW
a erew yehT .snagazaW fo draeh d'I ,yakO
.esuolb reh fo pot eht gninottubnu detrats ilA
,nomdliW retsiM uoy erA"
",tinu lortnoc a ot kcab gnillac s'tI
"?tis ot gniog uoy era erehW"
.erom tib a pu dekool I nehT "?…uoy …pleh I yaM"
”drowS dna ecneliS“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.erofeb yad eht tekram eht morf parcs rof pu dekcip d'I pmoc tekcop eht otni tiucric gnissecorp wen a gniredlos fo elddim eht ni saw I sa ,yletaidemmi retnuoc eht morf pu kool t'ndid I
"?kcen reh dnuora gniht taht s'tahw nehT" .dias I ",thgir llA"
,etunim a fo lla rof detsal noisiced tahT
"!noitar eirolac yliad ruoy nrae ot sksat deludehcs lla etelpmoc dna tinu krow ruoy ot nruter uoy stseuqer anihcaM xaP !tfihs krow detelpmoc tsal ruoy ecnis syad 320,4 neeb sah tI
.’retsiM‘ em sllac ereh dnuora ydoboN" .deilper I ",eoJ m'I"
a gnileef ,ylfeirb
.noitnetta rieht teg ot devaw I  .dias eh
ebyam ,kcen reh dnuora revlis gnimaelg fo gnir sselmaes a was I ,pu denepo ti sA
daor trid eht otno dna yab eht fo tuo su desae ilA ni depparts I sa noos sA .nwod delttes gnihtyreve dna rotareneg negordyh eht detrats ilA litnu htrof dna kcab tib a delbbob ti sa tsetorp ni denihw tinu varg s'ffiks eht ,ni debmilc aimaH nehW .taes regnessap eht otni debmilc dna deb ograc eht ni tikloot dna kcapkcab ym dessot I ".em rof skroW"   ".tfarc
regnol dna reprahs tol a erew yeht detcepsus I esuaceb ,did eh nehw hteet yna ffo wohs t'ndid eh taht yppah saw I dna
,semit eerht rednilyc eht tohs ehs dna
.deksa I "?pu s'tahW"
eht ot emoh ym morf delevart I sa ,ilA dnuof I erehw si tahT"
tuoba ta tuo pot d'eh
.anihcaM xaP fo lobmys tonk ebolirt eht htiw gnola
",elbissopmi eht sehsiw ehS"  .deksa I "?tahW"
noos ytterp tub ,dluoc I sa raf sa nar
si nalc yM" .detnurg aimaH
?sseug tseB"  .deksa aimaH
.srae elibom ,egral sih ni stfut yhsub htiw
ton enigami t'ndluoc I tub ,efil ym evas ot eton a dloh t'ndluoc I
eb dluow taht eno ,ydob reh hguorht kcohs rehtona dnes thgim ti
.won litnu ,sseltiurf demees kcen reh morf ralloc desrucca taht evomer dluoc taht ygolonhcet a dnif ot tseuq yM
,yrt ot gnilliw era uoy fi ecirp riaf a uoy yap nac I"
saw tner ym retfa kcab emoc t'ndid I fi stnetnoc eht lla fo gnisopsid
,ylreporp poleved ton did smurd
,niaga tfel ,kcab reh deklaw I
",uoy naht rellams si nwot siht ni enoyreve ,ydduB"
thguoht etunim tsal eht ta tub
.elbat eht no meht gnittes dna ralloc evitcani eht fo seceip owt eht tuo gnillup ,meht dlot I
.hguoht noituac rieht rof meht emalb t'ndluoc I
"?won erofeb ereht kcab og ot deirt reven uoY"  ".sdnal yrruf
.retnuoc eht ot detlob tpek I xob krow eht ni ti tes I .tiucric eht gnitelpmoc ,derettum I ",ces enO"
"?uoy no taht tup tinu xaP A"
.tsiaw sih dnuora liat gnol sih gnipparw
moc s'ffiks eht otni pmoc mlap ym deggulp I dna ,deddon ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.tcapmi s'ytic taerg eht gnirud deppord
"?krow t'nseod taht fi dnA"
,setag ytic sa devres skcod eht syadawoN
.nwod mih devaw I
.deb ograc eht ta liat sih gnivaw
,elcric revlis rehtona tuo gniward ,tleb sih ta hcuop eht otni dehcaer aimaH ".noitavacxe anihcaM xaP a fo sngis dewohs taht niur a gninimaxe elihw
,ylippah gnilbrub no tnew ti sA
.lotsip eldeen reh deretslohnu ilA
ni rentrap roinuj
.emarf rood eht no sdap regnif ym deppat I sa
,yaD ecyoR yb ”enO traP ,drowS dna ecneliS“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,no detlob stib citenrebyc htiw sklof
.seiceps tnereffid llA .gnuoy llA
.rehtegot gnidnirg setalp romra dna rehtael gnikaerc fo tol a evlovni ot demees
",neht syad fo elpuoc a ni uoy eeS"  ".laed riaf A"
.pis regnol a gnikat ,deilper I
.strac dnuorg dna sffiks rewols dnuora devaew ehs sa ,ilA deksa I
.edir ym rof dekool I sa dnuora egdod ot dah I taht
,secaf ruo otni gnikool saw ti fi sa
drows eguh sih tpews aimaH  "—ycer rof dereetnulov eb yam sksat etelpmoc ton od ohw stinu ecivreS !def llew era sksat rieht etelpmoc ohw stinU ecivreS"
.tuo tog eh sa revo ffiks eht pit ot ton tseb sih did dna flesmih htaenrednu morf tuo sgel sih delrucnu aimaH elihw ,hcterts doog a gnikat ,taes ym fo tuo dellor I
.xis regnol on era uoy tegrof I semitemoS
)su dnimer ot ti ediseb sngis fo ytnelp erew ereht dna
.nwoD arabmA ni sruf gnikool-llabddo fo tol a teg uoY  .erom tol a nehT
,yeboR nhoJ yb detide
.sreh ekil ralloc a yb dellik gnitteg fo raef rof
".detnaw uoy fi ,daor eht pu selim erom wef a su nur
",rereknit a m'I"  "?ralloc s'ilA
.dias aimaH ",ilA si sihT"
,gnis ot gnirad neve
"?thginK ggE na s'tahW"
,gniylf saw ytic eht nehw kcaB
.tlih drows sih fo og gnittel ,kcab gnikcilf srae ,reh ot dias aimaH ",yrros m'I"  .did yltnerappa nagazaW
,su morf yawa gnicaf
,sgniht gnikaerb tratS"
xaP tuB .erus ,semitemos gnikrow hcet NDNG dlo teg nac I" .mih dlot I
ereht ni tnew uoy fi ,kcul retteb evah thgim uoY"
.no tnew dna ,deddon ehS  .deksa I
.tnalp dettop a ron ,faed rehtien si ilA" ,dias
"?si ti erehw wonk t'nod uoY"
",stirips ni egludni t'nod I"
.enituor decitcarp ylsuoivbo na ni tuoba devom riap eht sa ,deksa I
.mih ta ti gnivaw ,seicnegreme rof ereht tpek I
,dias dna em ot kcab denrut eH ".xis
.stnar ruo htob gnitpurretni ,ria eht tilps
.daeh sih koohs neht dna ,denworf drazil eulb gib ehT
"?eert eht tuo gniwolloh
.gnikool t'nsaw I nehw edils ot dednet
.senihcam llams dliub ,sksat od ot thguat erew eW
,tnemom a rof hctaw ot revo decnalg ilA .wets ykrej dna naeb a pu gnikooc detrats dna ,top a otni guj citsalp egral a morf retaw deruop aimaH sa dehctaw I ".yakO"  .ecin si rehtaew eht fi tnet a htiw rehtob t'nod eW
,retnuoc eht no nwod notab nuts eht gnittes ,dias I
.su ekil yranecrem a ton
.selcric ni gniog pu dedne dna tsol tog I
lrans tnelis a ni sgnaf reh morf kcab deleep spil reH
.hcuop tleb rehtona otni gnihcaer ,dias aimaH ",eoJ
,hcet anihcaM xaP no trepxe na m'I
,deraor nagazaW eht "!revals on ma I"
".nosrep fo tros eltbus a ton m'I"
,em ta pu dekool ehS
.kcab sih ssorca gnuls drabbacs a ni
,gnidraugydob ,trocse navaraC"
,yrt ot erew ew fi raef I  dnA
.erifpmac a gnidliub detrats dna
.seceip owt otni nekorb wohemos tub ,s'ilA sa emas eht
",tuo erugif ot elba saw I tahw s'ereh ,yakO"
.nwoD arabmA fo htron skcilk derdnuh owt tuoba noitaton cificeps a ot detniop eH
ylerusiel a ta dnuorg eht gnola demmiks ffiks eht sa ezeerb ecin a saw ereht tub
rab eht morf spihc fo etalp a dna reeb a debbarg I
gnisu ,ti dnuora pu tliub sllaw sti nihtiw evil ot droffa t'ndluoc ohw sklof eht sa
snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT dna
.ilA ot denrut I
,seert eht sdrawot dedaeh I
,em htiw niamer ot reh gniwolla fo eciohc eht decaf I yllaniF
",yug a wenk ohw yug a wenk ohw yug a morf ,oot taht draeh I ,haeY"
".dluoc I tseb sa reh desiar dna
.emarf eguh sih tif ot rehtegot detevir
"!noitasucca ruoy yb dednuow ylpeed ma I .taes s'revird eht ni tif t'nod ylerem I !yzal ton ma I"
.arabmA dlO fo egde eht no kcod yks nretsew eht ta ilA dna aimaH tem I  .aedi trams a fo noitinifed s'eno on si hcihw
.eunitnoc ot aimaH rof gnirutseg ,dehgis neht dna ,ecno daeh reh koohs ehS  "?etum yllarutan
,moc.nozamA hguorht elbaliava
.div lacirotsih a fo tuo ydobemos ekil deklat yeht taht ron
.ebyam egaugnal evitan sih —ezingocer t'ndid I tpircs gniwolf a htiw sraey eht revo detatonna dna deniats ,oga gnol erehwemos detnirp ,kcap sih morf pam citsalp egral a tuo dellup aimaH  .noitsuahxe
deriuqer ruoy si tahW"
.sebuc nedoow elttil esoht lla sdeen tahw teem ot tnaw uoy fi ylnO"
.evila erew yeht fi ,stnerap reh ot ilA nruter dna ,htrib fo ecalp reh dnif ot detpmetta tsrif I .oN"
.kcab denrut srae ym sa gnihsal liat ym ,taps I
,kcab dna ereht ot doof dna
.reeb ym fo pis lufthguoht a koot I
,drowS dna ecneliS“   yojne esaelP
.won thgir detnaw ehs tahw t'nsaw ylbaborp regnarts raen a yb dehcuot gnieB .ti fo retteb
,lotsip reh fo retsloh eht no wap eno dna pu srae
",ssarG tfoS fo yellaV eht fo ,enotsdnaS nalC fo thginK ggE ,aimaH ma I" 	        "?uoy era lleh eht tahW ?uoy era lleh eht ohW
ot deirt I .ylpmis dias eh
,yleugav ylnO  .reh deksa I
,ilA ot revo dekool aimaH
”,sselhtrow ton saw tI“
".sexof fo ylimaf a htiw reh ecalp tsael ta ot detpmetta dna pu evag I
.ylfeirb detrons aimaH  .deksa I
.reh ot taht od t'ndluoc I"
.taht eveileb nac I"
ylimaf liatkraD eht fo sevil citnamor eht gnitacilpmoc si ecyoR
.steewt kciuq owt ,ylprahs eltsihw ilA draeh ew sa pu dekcirp srae ruO
.aimaH ta pu gniralg ,spil reh morf sregnif reh werdhtiw ilA
.redlo nworg s’ehs sa emoceb sah ti thgit woh nevig yllaicepse
"?os yas uoy t'ndid yhw ,yakO"
,sraet htiw tew seye nedlog
dna tserof eht otni depacse I
".taht ta doog rehtar m'I
neht dna ,mih ot detniop ehS .ilA deksa eh "?rennid ekam ot ti si nrut esohW"
,tuo dna ni ciffart toof gnillortnoc
,srekaeps eht hguorht gnipmup taeb cissalc ecin a dah I nooS  .tinu
erew smeti rehto fo elpuoc
.daerht eht pu gnikat ,dias aimaH
noitatropsnarT"  "?tnemyap
"…dias tsuj uoy tuB"
",ti ekil erom si nwod s'tahW"
.erom ecno em dewollof ehs dna
,"desolC" ot rood eht no ngis eht nrut ot retnuoc eht dnuora deppets ,flesym ot denworf I .llis rood wol eht no daeh sih gninaeb ton wohemos aimaH ,pohs ym tfel snoinapmoc dehctamsim owt ehT .meht dlot I
.yaw eht ni teg naht rehtar slanoisseforp eht ot evael ot retteB
…od ot noissim a no setimret lacinahcem ,egreme meht fo nezod owt revo dehctaw I
,elcihev ro tobraw a ebyam
a htiw tub ,selacs eulb ynit fo sdnasuoht fo desopmoc niks htiw
deipucco pohs ym gnidliub eht tfel ti ,oga sraey evif-ytrof dnuorg eht tih arabmA nehW
,kniht I ,dlo sraey xis saw ilA"
.esuolb reh fo ralloc eht dehcuot dna eugaelloc reh ta pu dekool ehs
;ti htiw no gniog s'tahw tuo erugif ot nepo esac eht pop t'ndluoc I"
notab nuts eht pu thguorb dna retnuoc eht rednu dehcaer I
,seires serutnevdA nexiV deR
ot langis s'ralloc eht esu ot sehsiw ehS"
tuo gnillup ,deb ograc s'ffiks eht morf gab egral a debbarg dna dehgual aimaH
?tuo siht erugif dluoc uoy kniht uoy oD" .dias aimaH
sirbed eht hguorht gniggid dnif dluoc yeht esle revetahw ro parcs
.raf os seog ylno noisiv thgin s'drapoel a neve tub
",evals s'eno on si ilA"
,erus rof saw taht ,lacol t'nsaw tnecca siH .tib a tsehc nwo ym koohs
.raer eht ni deb ograc derevocnu egral
,trohs saw ehs ,llat ylsuolucidir saw nogard eulb
aimaH ,em dlot ehs
.thgin eht flah gnivird pu dedne I
".ereh dnuora kcab liat eulb gib ruoy gnirb uoy t'nod dna ,uoy no drauG s’tceferP eht llac I erofeb pohs ym fo tuo teG
.reh dlot I ",ton ebyaM"
a dna ralloc ehT
"?naem siht seod tahW"
.desirprus eb ot ton gnidneterp ta boj retteb a did snamuh lacol dna seirruf ehT
dah ohw ,ilA fo tnorf ni deppots eW  ".evissergga
,noitartsurf ni dias dna placs sih hguorht wap ytaem eno
.srevals htiw laed t'nod I"
.sdoog ro sregnessap daolnu ro daol ot kcod dluow sffiksria erehw syab eguh ruof fo eno saw ti
fo erac ekat osla d'yehT
,dehgis ehs nehT .aimaH yb deyaler sa ,em ot derutseg ilA ,eromyna ton tub ,evals a saw I
.tnemeerga ni ylmrif gniddon nexiv eht ,dias aimaH
.nit parcs morf detcurtsnoc ratiug a dna ,murd but a ,sepip citsalp fo edam stnemurtsni desivorpmi no taeb elbaecnad a gnipmuht
,erutseg ym tA
peed eht ni gnignuorcs morf pohs ym ni ffuts eht fo tsom tog I tuB"
,ti ta ekop dna ytilicaf anihcaM xaP a rof kool yletarebiled ot gniog osla saw I tub ,ereht tuo efil ym gnisol no erugif t'ndid I .eud
?gnithgif draeh evah I t'ndluohs ,regnad saw ereht fI
.hsal liat ym tlef I  .dias aimaH
".dleh saw ehs erehw ytilicaf eht dnif
.egaugnal eht fo tser eht gniwonk tuohtiw neve ,etalsnart ot ysae saw mih evag ehs erutseg txen ehT
".ytilicaf eht ni saw yltcaxe IA eht erehw tniopnip
,enO raeY :tcejorP noitamalceR ehT
?neht ,reh ffo ti tuc uoy t'nevah lleh eht yhW"
sdrawot drawtuo gnidael
.derutseg dna em ta decnalg ilA
a dna seye nedlog thgirb htiw nexiv a saw ehS
,llat saw I sa gnol sa tuoba drows ssendoog ot tsenoh na ekil dekool tahw fo eldnah eht was I dna ,kaolc etihw dehctap dna deniats a erow eh romra eht revO
.wenk reven tsuj uoy anihcaM xaP eht htiW
,sdrawpu detlit rednilyc ehT
a ot kcab sih nwod yaw eht lla diarb ypor a otni nward riah der thgirb fo daeh
tsuj deniag eb ot gnihton saw erehT
a dna ,seirruf dezis egareva rof staes owt erew erehT .gninwa nolyn
".seert eht hguorht sepoh eugav htiw dnuora gnilbmuts
,elgna eerged evif lauteprep a ta tneb
”,anihcaM xaP s'tI"  .deksa I "?yhW"
,re ,s'ilA htiw neve ,ni reh ekat ot gnilliw naht erom saw dnuof I ylimaf ehT .on ,hO"
rae esohw ereht ynam era ereht ,tluser a sA
.no gnimoc ehcadaeh
,senihcam gnikniht eht yb seilimaf rieht morf yawa nekaT
.niaga riah sih hguorht swalc sih nar aimaH  ".reh