.detnaw reve I lla s’taht dna“
meht fo yna was reve tdleftatS ni enoN
.ti gnidnatsrednu ot esolc os saw ynahteB ”
.ytiminanu esiwrehto rieht kaerb ot gnihton did tnemeergasid siht tuB .yenruoj gnol a
,sedaced revo ,ylbativeni
.enog saw retfird eht dna ,deniamer tdleftatS fo elpoep ehT
.ssuf tuohtiw ssalg eht detpecca etoyoc ehT
-erofeb mih ta detniop slerrab eerht eht ees dna pu kool ot emit ylno dah kcud gnittis ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,eert mulp laref a rof evas
”,lleweraf yas ot emit si ti fI“
,flah a dna eno rO
,worros elbarusaemmi na htiw dednelb saw tI
,delttesnu tib a er’yeht knihT
,htimS .srM saw sA
,tdleftatS fo htaed elbativeni eht raeh dluoc ehs ti nI
,nwod elttes dna elleb nwot eht fo traeh eht niw
̶̧͔̈́̑͛̚ņ̴̠̩͐̔͛̔ͅw̷̡̤̖͍͕̌̍o̶͉͉͊̚D̷̫͎̓͒͌̓̓͜n̵͉̟̈́̒̈̌r̴̡̛͎̗̘̫͌́͠ȏ̵̢̪̥̳̱T̴̙̅̄e̷̩̎͋͋̈̔ŗ̴́̍̉e̵̢͎͗̕͠W̶̧̰̫̙͆̃̉̾̇ͅs̵̢̫̹̿̑̆͝p̶̭̰͖̅̃̂̍͠ö̸͚̩͎̹̱h̵͇͇̰͉͋Ŝ̷͎͕̇̑d̴̦̠̫̉͂l̵̡̢̲̻͎̀̕Ȯ̶̧̂e̵͍̣̲̊̋͊͗̕r̴̳͙̣̰̽ĕ̷̗̣͜h̶̲̣͕͆̿W̶̢̠͐̄͘͝s̸͚͂͜t̴̢̧̲̄̕ǫ̴̛̬͔̖̊͘͘Ḽ̶̟̣̆͗̀͂ë̷̗̰̘͔̄͒̆͘ͅh̸̢̜̻͉̘͆̑T̷͓̮̝͉̻̈́̆̑ņ̷̎̔͛͌̚I“ .nosinu suorednuht ni
,desserd-ylprahs ,mussop
.emoh sih tub erehwyna tser ot detnaw evah t’ndluow eh—
,eerga dluow ynahteB dnA
.niaga emoh doohdlihc reh ni toof tes reven dna reh dniheb srood eht dekcol ehs nehT
”.̷̙̤̉̈́̊̿͝d̷̪͕̜͇̗̈́̈́n̴͍̗̻̯̗̓̇i̷͓̽͐̊͒͠h̴̠͑e̴͚̬̺͕̋B̸̟̥͉̱̾̽̀̈́ͅĕ̸͎̏̽̔r̵͓͐͗͊ȩ̶̢̝̑́̈́h̴͚͛̔̇̋̿ͅw̸͈͓͚̾̍e̵̗̜̯͎̤͌̓̇̚͠m̸̟̝̖͚͐̽ǫ̷͎̯̟̾̽̆̏̈́S̶̰͚͉̓͛̓͆͝ś̴͍̲̈́I̵̧͇̋͜͝e̵͓͕͝H̸̭̖̝͔͊̆̓y̴̨̝͋́k̷̝̋̏S̶̢̥̼̬̙͆̾͝ę̷͇̼͖̐͌̀h̸̻̺͇̎̐̿̈́͠T̵̟̍̀̓̐̽s̶̢̟̦͚̓̈́̓̑I̸̖̓̈ṫ̴͇͋̈̏ă̷̗̙͖̙͜͝ḩ̵̥̘̬̿T̶̠̬͍̑̋̊̀͠d̸͈̤̥͕̤̒́̓͂͠n̷̯̽̊̽A“
.reverof ti fo trap a erew yeht hceeps
,nethgiarts mussop dlo eht nees evah dluow yeht
,trofmoc ni ,tsal ta
,ytsud dna dehsaw knis eht yb sehsid
”̸̠͗̆̾e̶̝̓̆̂z̵͓̜̲͈͒i̴̜̱̲̻̾̈́̎͝S̵̺͖̗͐̚ĺ̵̰̩͎̀̿͜a̸̬̋͋ù̵̻̰͈͔̜̚s̸̛͍̯̝̺̀̓ṳ̶̢̆n̶̨̗̉̅̇͠Ṳ̴̬͐́̽f̷̪͋͗͛O̶̞̯͎̅̃́͘h̵̢̺̜̤̯͆̽ṱ̴͋̍̔͝ȩ̸̞̘̈́̌e̸̬̜͒Ṭ̶͕̟̼̖̌̆̈́̓́s̴̬̤̟͍̫̓̑̍͝i̵̢̱̾͐͌̆H̴̬̠͉͋͗̈̎͠e̷͇̍͆̌r̵̢̺̲̩̮̐̇̏̈́͝Ä̷̡̬́͜ȩ̷̪͐͋͑̇ͅs̵̡̜͒̅͜e̶̘̮̺̬͆̐͒͋̚ẖ̴̛̥̫̫͋͋T̶̪̞̈̂͐̈́̕s̵͍͙̟̈́ę̶̨̖͚̅̐͊̂y̶̪̑͛Ę̸͔̬̤̬͘s̶̝̥̗͖̜͌i̵͖̟̲̗̐Ĥ̵͉ē̶̜̲r̷͓̺̈̏̕y̵̤̝͙̟̝̿̓e̶͓̮͎͐̓̋̃h̷̛͎̊͛̉T̴̢͇̞̻̬̅́͝d̵̞̂n̷͍͝͠e̶̞̱̋͐͝ͅţ̷̲̯̆͘ḙ̸̥̠̽̄r̶̦̀̾̈̋͠P̴̛͓͛̏͠ţ̵̲̦͎̹͗ȗ̶͔̟̰̰̓̕B̸͖̖͂̆̔̍̓s̵͓͐̇͐̿̈e̶̯̥̔p̸̹͈̟̄̈́̀a̴̩̅͠ŗ̶͍̖̀̍̀͝G̴̡͎̫̈̀͂ḏ̴̉́̒́e̵̢̧͉̼͂l̷̜̆͂͘̚͠e̶̜͔̝̝̓̈́̐e̶̙͑̈́͛P̶̣̗̭̎e̶͔͘r̴̢̞̝͊̀̎͘A̸̗͇̿e̶̢͍̩̖̓̆̊͠s̶̟̑̕e̸̝̦̙͊͌̆̂̾ḩ̶̛͇̽͑͋T“
̷͕̝͑ḑ̸͕̼̜̯̫͓̃̎͆̆͘ṉ̷̡͇̩̟̓͐̈́̓̌͠į̵̡̼̖̫͉̠́̄͗̅͆͝h̷̨͇̜̩̕e̶̦̭̝̱̖͇̍̏B̸̡̯̙͈̂͐͑̚͠͝y̴̛̻̯͍̐̄̿͊̇̅ǎ̵͙̒͋͆͋̂̋w̷̑͐̍͂͒͝ͅh̴̡̢̼̩͓͖̹̄̅̌ğ̴͕́ï̵͕H̵̙̗̤͍͕́͌̑̎͠͝e̵̞̔̆̈́̎̌h̵̪̓̓̈́̽T̸̥̂̀̌̄̓͠e̴̻͋̓v̷̜̥̲̥͈͈͆̆͆̈́͒͋̂a̶̝͍̱̞̼͂̅̀ę̵̬̖̝̱͓̒̊̀̿̃̕͝L̸̡̡̖̗̆̈̇̅͌l̸̙̘̞̣͕͉̤̿͋̀l̸̢͓̒͝I“ .lufituaeb saw ti dnA .gnignis saw ehs
,gnirolpxe ,gnilevart ,gnivael tuoba
deen eht tlef nwot elohw eht
.dniw fo tsug neddus a htiw fi sa
”̷̮̔͝͝h̷̖̿t̶̡̢͈̰͋̿́̋ä̷̱́́͝ê̶̯͌̒͆̚D̷̫͆̀͊͗s̸͓̮̹͖͔͘i̷̩̼͗̈̐͘Ḥ̵̪̠̽̅̈́͆s̶̻̠͙̯̄͂̍̿I̴̬̬̙̎s̶̼̪͊̑͂̑͐ȋ̷̡̢̞̝̉́̚̚h̷̤̓T̷̪͉̩̼͒g̵̯͙̉ͅṉ̶̱̥̾̀̇͜͠i̴̩͓̾͛̀v̸̼̄́̏͜i̵͇̽L̸̫̼̦̜͗s̶͍̦̈́̈́͌í̴̞̮̻͙̒̒̎̚Ḩ̴̣̻̓̊̽̅̎ș̵̓̃ą̶̱̘̼̲͆͘W̵͔̓̈͜͠t̵̻̭̟̻̊͂a̸̱͕͎͓͛̒̓̀h̸͉̼̓̕͝T“
,yrots gib eht tnaem taht dna
.ti tog dniw eht erehw yas t’ndluoc tub
,kcaJ namstocS ,nnamitliT fo secaf eht no sa hcum os ton tuB ”̴̙̎̆́́͝ͅd̵̀̅͑͋ͅo̴̖̊̿͒͜o̴̡̡̜͌͜l̸͚̬̑̑̏͋̅B̶̭̮̃͐͘͘s̶̘̑̎͆̀͘ì̴̪͖͇̮̂H̶̼̪̦͆̊̄͆͛s̸̛̞̝͚̱͔̃̓Î̸̳̞̭̼̳̽s̵̟̦͉̃͛͂͜i̴̟̩̇̒́̈́h̷͈͎̺͂͜T” .tdleftatS fo klofsnwot eht fo tser eht fo
nigeb ot hguorht gnippets dna
eert mulp eht rednu syad tneps
dellup nward htaerb yreve
.rohtua eht yb daeR
,devom dna ,dekool yehT
”.knird ot gnihtemos ekil dluow I“
dniw eht no ti draeh ohw ,floWcaM boR yb
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf seigolohtna ni
.og ot tnaem erew sgniht woh morf tnereffid os ton saw siht esnes a ni dnA
?ti ssucsid ot stiw hguone deniater dna
,dallab ydwab a eb ot yloh oot saw ti
,ssarg gnol eht hguorht sevaw decart
,tsaf ylgnikcohs delbmurc flesti tdleftatS dna ,cisum eht ni gnillornu saw erutuf eht won dna ”̴̼̝̩̳͑̈e̴͚̟̖̥̅̌̑̑̈́r̵̨̭̞̙͌o̶̮̫̳͊m̵̬̝͙̏̓̇͘y̴͉͊͝͝n̷̞̮̹͎̈́̎A̵͎̫̅̂͠t̸̟̓̈́̒͝ḧ̵̲́̂g̴̨͕̤̻̜͒͝ḭ̵̯̱̎͑͘ͅļ̶͎̆ñ̶͔̳̑̅̑u̶̧̅̽S̷̨̜̮̻̄͆è̷̖̙̿h̴̻̜͛̓͠͠T̷͉̲͇̽r̸̨̬̥̒ã̶̜̺̠̩͐͝͝͠e̴̦͌̓̆̐͜F̵̝̂ţ̴̘̻̾͆̎n̵̡͖̑̉o̷̞̝̱̣̲̐͛͋̇̀W̷̜̺͆̆̒̆̚Ḯ̶͕̥͕͕͝d̴̘̬̓͂͌̎̊ͅn̶̘̺̹̽́̆̚͜A“
.lausunu saw mrof rieht esac siht ni hguoht railimafnu ton si dliub yeht yrots eht dna
,ytidicul ot kcab sevlesmeht ekahs dluoc enoyna erofeB .niaga
.slavir ’stnerap reh rof skrow ohw dnah hcnar derih eht
.pohsrebrab eht morf ssorca
.nwardhtiw neeb dah esoprup dna lliw lla hcihw morf sregnif morf deppils slotsip
yletal ohw nem erew eseht
,nialpxe ot decudni eb dluoc ehs naht erom wenk ylraelc ohw yadakceH eiggaM dna
alopuc eht no enavrehtaew eht morf
ylnepo dah htimS .srM
,stsixe raef stegrof yletelpmoc taht regna fo dnik eht otni noitartsurf dnoyeb dessap dah ynahteB ”,lleW“
dooh dna ohcnop deroloc-tsud a ni etoyoc niht A
rood tnorf eht gninepo ekil erom tlef ti taht deilper dah ynahteB hcihw ot
.ni nioj ot ytisoiruc yb nevird erew siuL dna ynahteB
,denepo ylerab spil siH
deliaf sah od nac yeht tseb eht retfa dna ,sdrow otni ti tup ot elggurts eht nigeb yeht erofeb snaem elat rieht tahw swonk relletyrots a ro teop a yaw eht tnaem ti tahw wenk ehs tuB
,pots elbailer a sa ecalp eht no yler ot emac
”?siht si tahw dnA“
.eert mulp eht rednu niamer dluow siuL dna ynahteB
,noolas eht drawot devom dworc ehT
.tsethgils eht ni dnim ot mees ton did eH
rof dehsiw d’eh taht
.knird sih morf pu kool ton did retfird eht tuB .spahrep
,rettel a deviecer ytiC sasnaK ni
,reh rof tnaem saw sdrow eht ni gnihtemos taht noitiutni eht ekahs ton dluoc ehS
”̷͓̘̲͛d̵̢̡̧̦̹̑͝n̶͙̱̩̓͒̈́͊ị̴̒̌̌̀M̵͈̒s̸̫̝̻̲͈̋i̵̢̻͖͓͉͘̕Ḥ̸͓͖̻̯̑̒̾f̶͉̟͉̼͊̎̈Ǫ̸̧̩̿͗͋̆t̴̔ͅf̷̖͐̽e̷̋̐̊ͅL̸̡͇̫̇͛̕e̵̛͖̣̯̻̲͌͋̅͘r̸̨̩̘͖̹͛̾̀̎̂Ḁ̵̥̮̯̌̀̅t̶̒̔ͅa̷̜͇͇̭̓̈́̋h̶̡̧̺̻͇͋̈́̐̕T̴͙̝̣̯͉͆̾̓̓s̵̨̭̯̝̔͒͗̎͠d̷̼͇͖̤̪̃͊͝͠r̵̛͇͑́̃o̷̗̞̠͐͗̌͝W̵̙͉̓̎ȅ̴̮̻̞̼͎h̶̡͛̿̇̐Ṱ̷͖̹̞̿̉̒̆͠e̷͔͉̻̭͛̂r̴̺͔̈̒A̵͇̳̪̞͌ẹ̸̽s̸̹̺͇̻͂̕ͅé̴̡̱̊̒ḧ̸̞͙͚T“
.repeeknoolas eht degru yadakceH srM
,wenk seiriarp eht no devil ohw enoyna taht
”̸̦͇̲̍̓̌̈́e̷̹̝̜̼̹͂̒͛r̴͕͉͓̰͗́̈́̈́̾o̶̩̲̕h̴̨̩̜̍̐̊̈͘S̷̡̎̽̚l̴̢̧̡̞̇̅á̵͚̬̮̰̇̕͘p̶͍̀͘O̶̥͔̺̍͆́̍̕ě̶͙̼̈͛̈͛h̵͕̓̈́̽Ṭ̸̡̫̗͙̑̾o̸̢̻̓̌T̷̝̹̉̆͐̍ǹ̷̛̳̱̖̫͇̅͆͘w̵͙̱̺̯̾̈̊͆͗o̶̖͎̫͘D“ .oot
.srebmemer dniw eht derussa ma I tuB
.kcohs ni ylno saw ti
.seye sih esolc dna
,ekaL tlaS ni noitats cificaP noinU eht morf detsop
,tuhs swodniw eht
won dootsrednu ehs yhw ro
.ytilitsoh nrob saw egairram hguor rieht fo dna
,ogacihC ni sreredrum htiw knurd
,tsew tuo eriter ot tnaem ehs
.yawa wolb dluoc lios eht erofeb evarg eht elttes ot
nnamitliT dewollof ylihtlaets ,drazil denroh a dna epoletna na
uoy rof ecalp a ylno saw ereht hcihw nI
wodniw tnorf a tuo kool ot
evaH“ .niaga ekops retfird eht ,tnemom a retfA
,dezeeuqsnu sreggirt ,ezorf snuG
.delffab dna ediw seye
” ̶͙͔̠̝̄̽̄̒̄͠r̸̫̙̰̓e̸̤̥̫̫͇͊v̴̠͖̗͙̤̔͒̃̓͐̀̏ȩ̵̜͚̘̦̟̈́̅r̸͇͓̹̆̎o̵̡̢͍̬̙̒̓͛̌F̵̛̖̌̓̀̓̀̃d̷̬̆͑͆͗̈́n̵͎̠̺̙̤̈́͆̀͝A̵̡͚͆̈́̽ṕ̷̡̙̖̥̓͒̂̈́̕͠ȋ̴̟̃̑̕͝ḣ̴̡̬̞̻̰̻͎͆͠Ş̸̝͈̺͎̞͈̈̓̈́̑̂e̵͖̽͌̔h̴̼̳̔͆̽T̶̬͇͙͉̤̉̌̈͘ȇ̴̖̉̍̚k̶̹̟̉̿̚a̴̲̬͌̀̚T̷̯͙̪͕̍̀͝͠l̶̢̦̾̓̀͋͜l̸̹̝̝̻̏̋ͅI“ .detcepxe yleritne erew ti fi sa saw ti
tnacav deniamer dnal eht yletamitlu os
,ralucitrap ni ,retfird enO ”.detnaw
,siuL ot gnidroccA
,god.ecioveht ta
.tsrif ti od ot denimreted erofereht dna
,desserp fi ,edecnoc ot evah dluow trebelgnE coD neve taht ro
,gnitraped ni ,stnediser ynaM
.ereht dnuof eb ot skoob fo noitcelloc a fo noissessop ekat dna
ytuaeb ylhtraenu fo tnerrot a rednu trapa gnillaf
,seirots rehto eht lla yrub ot tnaem nem hcir hcihw rednu
,yellaV aibmuloC eht ro ,nogerO ni
,yliraw ,rehtohcae eye ot nageb yllaicepse owt
.tnelis llef muh ehT
”.ytsriht ma I dna“
̷̠̺͉̱̱̲͓͑̇ḑ̴̠̪̩̤̊̀̐̀n̶̰̭̗̰̄̊́̔̚͘͜ḯ̷̥̫̰͈̖Ẅ̵̙̰̥̩̯͎̩́̂ẻ̷͚͎̭̩̓̍͗̾h̷̫̺̮͔̳͊̋͌͘͝ͅT̷̡̖̦͍͌͐̈́̚ḧ̸̙̖̟̙́ͅṱ̴͒͗̔̎̈́͌i̷͓͙͘W̴̠̤͌ě̵̢̝̖͕͛͗͜r̶̩̫̹̣̬̊͐̕͜ȇ̸̲͉̌̊͂̉͊ͅh̶͚̖̹̣͔͍̅́͝ͅŤ̶̤͈̬ͅͅt̵̨̬̦͂̏u̵͎̯͓̼͕͊̑̌̅̎͜͝͝O̴̡̰͔̼̎́̋̃̾̔̕ͅe̴̛̳̥̠r̸̮̭͔̈͊̐̕ͅe̶̡̨͓̔̆̄̎̐̐͝ḩ̶̼̈́̌́̈̽̈w̷̼͖͍̠͈͕͊e̸̻͔̱̙̋̀m̸͖͈̳̻̾͑̃̓̿̈̍ò̵͚̼͐Ś̶̛̖̞͎͖͚̲͔̑e̶̩̞̙̙̙͊̏̍̋͝B“  ,gnos eht deifilpma rehtar tub tuo nword ton did dna
,floWcaM boR yb ”eM hguorhT dna
,hsirag ,wolloh ,eslaf
.derettam regnol on ti ,esruoc fo ,emit taht yB
,yap nettog-lli sih fo noitrop a tnes llits eh mohw ot
:rovivrus ylno eht si dna
.denrut nemnug eht fo hcae
,ylbatciderp dna ylbatrofmoc yrev rehtegot tif taht seceip era eseht
.seirots ni ylno neppah sgniht hcuS
,senevretni regnarts suoiretsym emos tub ,tpure ot snetaerht nem sselwal dna tneloiv gnoma muucav rewop ehT
.dworc eht ni enoemos detuohs ”!no og
̵̬̲̎̔̔ȩ̴̠̮̻̮͚́ͅm̵͓̾̾̈́̔̚õ̴̜͐̄̾̔H” ” ̴̛̟̲̗̩̏̃̅̾̏̕y̶͉͕̾̋l̴̨̐̎̏l̶̯̫͓̤̫̒̒̇̉ͅa̸̢̢̜͔̾̀̓͒͂n̷͍͎̫̳͉̔͑̎́̎͒͜i̴͇̙̘̹͒̾̿̈́̚̕͝F“ ” ̶̡̡͇̞͇̖̾͑̋̃̇e̸̱̪̬̗̘̯͛́͆̊̂B̴̤̭̙̌̃̏l̸͈̆͛̀̎ͅḽ̶̈́Ĩ̶̬̯̏͛̎̀̚ȩ̸̨̢̰̮̅́̿͆͘r̷̥̤̖̖̤̎͒͘͝ȩ̶̝̫͚̝̩͐ḥ̸͕̜͚̟͂̀͂͘͝Ẃ̸̨̄̑̒̚̚s̴͎͉̿t̸̛̟̖̞͕͇̊̌̾̾ả̷̠̩̝̃̈h̵͙̰̣̐̔T“ ?odanrot a yb trapa nwolb kcatsyah a ekiL
.demrof dah nemnug ruof eht elcric eht dnuora esiwkcolcretnuoc deklats retfird ehT
.fo nuf edam gnieb erew eh fi sa dednuos coD
.noissucsid civic desufnoc dna deirruh emos saw ereht ereH
,daeh a ot emac yllanif mrots eht nehW
.yltfos gnas retfird eht ”̶̹̬̮͖͆̊͒̇ͅs̸̺͎͋d̸͇̓̂͑̇n̷̢̤̺͓̅̊̚a̷͚̭̔͗͗S̶̢̺̫͔̩̆n̵̢̤̬̱͗̏̓͘e̴͚̬̥̖͉͑́̋k̴̘̙̤̋̇̓̂l̸͉̲͂̇̏ĩ̴͖S̵͎̾̉̋̐ë̴̙͉̱̠́̔̅̾h̵͚͆̿T̸͙͓̕ǹ̶̻̰̲̜̂̈́̚͝o̴͇̲̾̔͊̿̍p̵̩͎̩̗̖̈́Ů̷͎͔́̚s̷̢̽́̀́͐ẻ̷̛͔̳͇v̶̗̑̓̋̕ȃ̷̩͇̥̞̐Ẅ̶̟̪͉͇̰́̊̅͛̕e̶̖̪͇̞̊h̵͓̹̐̂̓͆T“
.noitilov nwo reh fo
.swor taen ni erew
.emit tsrif eht rof mussop eht ta gnikool fi sa ,denrut eH
.gniwollib saw ohcnop s’retfird ehT ”
.trebelgnE coD dna mih neewteb ylluferac gnidnats llits
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dedaf cisum eht tuB ”
,nwot ni eciov yreve gnas ”
.draeh reven dah ynahteB seman esohw
.dnim reh ni pu delbbub noislupmoc oN
,tsomerof ,tsrif ta ,erew ohcnop deroloc-tsud eht ni etoyoc eht fo sgnithgis deromuR
,dleheb yeht elihw ,sgniht eseht gnus dah eh nehw dnA
.htaed naht regnortS
taht ecnarussaer hguone saw
peelsa nem ekil ton
.seirraH nomoloS yb gnireenigne lacisuM
,yadot ,era seirots esoht erehw swonk dniw eht tub enoyna fI
.yrots a rof egnahcxe ni
nees evah dluow yehT .mrots gnimoc dna dniw eht fo ecaf eht otni
,llaf ot reven tub desiop sremmah
,gnag taht gnimrof ni selor egral deyalp dah ssibroC dna shtimS eht htob taht dessucsid ton ylluferac saw tI
,seinorc owt dna kcaJ namstocS ,rehtaR
,dengiser dah htimS royaM
”̴̡̖̞̺̐͛d̶̢̝̮͓͈̋͗̍o̶̥̣̭͔̫͆͛́̏̈o̷̲̟̖͙͂̄ͅW̴̜̫̯̲͋͌͗̕f̸̙͂͒͑̽͜͝O̴͎̜͔̍t̴̛̼͔̤̀̏̓́͜u̴̫̿͑̀͌̀Ỏ̴̼̈́̕ͅd̷͇͙̘͍̿͊e̶̱̞͎̟͘͜v̴̧̭́r̴̪̳͍̩̲̐́ã̵͖̼̦̆̈́C̸̹̉͛͌̓̚ý̵̢̮̥̇̾ḝ̸̟̒͗̐͌ͅḩ̵̞̤̩̳̄͒̃͝T̵͍͍̪͖̺̆t̷̝̖̙̙͒̐a̵̛͎̮̝͉͝h̸͙̥̗͈͓͐T̵̠͇̓͜͝͠t̵̟͆r̴̝̼̮͌͋͠a̸̳͆͋̈̋͑ȅ̶̱̈͆̿H̵̨͎͔̋̒s̷̙͎̤̺̎ͅi̷̦͈̝͕͝ͅH̵̡̙̙͎̆͜͝s̷̭̉̐̿Ĭ̵̥̤͍͌͘s̴̠̮̣̙͙̓̓ḯ̸͎̺̬̟̆̈́h̶̯̍̎T“ .sgniht esoht fo lla ro yna saw ti yned ot rewop on dah ehs tub ,tnahc nagap emos eb ot erup oot saw ti
,yrarbiL ytiC sasnaK eht fo mooR yellaV iruossiM eht ot detanod erew
.derdnuh wef a ylno ,egral ton saw tdleftatS fo noitalupop ehT ”
,nrow dah sregoR efaR ekil hcum
.erofeb t’ndah ehs nehw
;sdniw eht yb pu nekat saw eh
,sreh ediseb ,dnim sih ro ,mih leef dluoc ehs dezilaer dna
,tnahpmuirt dna gnillirht saw cisum ehT ” ̵͎́͗͐́́͘e̴̡͙̰̙̭̿̓M̵̤̤̜̌̈́͜r̵̨̡̰̱͐̎͐̾̿o̵̢̥̣̠̜̮͉̔́̒̈́̅F̴͚͓̰̔͌̉̾͘g̷̦͖̩̭̣͌̍̆n̴̨̫̮̉͂ȉ̶͈̄̌̐̍̀̚t̴̙̞̻͉̬͑̀̍̾̐i̷͍͈͊͆̏͒a̶͇̝̙͚̰̺̭͆̈́̍͂̾Ẅ̷̼͕̱̠̣͎́̌̇͜͝ę̵̻̙̞̖̫͈͐̃̇͛͆͠B̸̹̂͌̓̃̕l̵̢̮͇̹̞̭̳͗̈́̓l̵͚̞̺̿͋ḭ̴̡͔̜̮̞̩̋̃̾̓W̶̙̠̻̤͒̏̒p̸̨͎̥͔̯̙͍̓̀͝í̸̤̎h̵̟͕̏̒̓͂̈́͊͝S̶͖̱̟͂A“ .ytimne rieht ro
.stluser yrotalihinaohcysp—
”,bat ham no ti tup dna daeh‘ og uoY“
,ecreif dna ,lufrewop saw gnos sihT
”̷̝̂̍̈́́͝e̵̥̺̜̕ŗ̴͇͖͕͂o̸̘͖͆̍̑̉̌M̷̡̡̝͂̈́̐͘̕ŏ̸̬͈̈͠N̷̬̮̜̠̂͊͝ͅm̶͕̥͕̉ě̸̞̝̫h̸̩̤͐Ț̴̲͂̓͝͝ś̵̟̘̍̓d̸̛̲̉̇̓ḙ̵̰̝̭͛͌͂̈́e̷͚̖̦̗͓͒N̶̬͈̺̥̠̄̽̊ẽ̸̡̤̠̼̏̑͐̀H̶̩̲̣̒̄͋͂͘h̸̢͔̮̠̦̋̍͋̾g̴̛͎̺̗͇̓̾́̆u̴̧̞͎͓̿̈̄͌͝ͅö̶̱͔̙͇́̅͗h̶̞͆̊͝T̵̳̞̻̭͚̀s̵̨͕̱̱̐̿̅͝é̷͇̼̰̣̞̃̾́h̶͕̙̪̝͇̉͗̀̐t̶̲̝̋ͅô̴͈̬l̶̼̜̲͆̓͒̈̉C̶̳̗̮͌̍̀̂̚s̷̳͗̇ȉ̸̛͎̥̹̈́͑͊͜H̷̫̗̍ȩ̷̣̤̙͇̌̈́͒͘ŗ̶̤̭̗̓͒͂A̸͚̖̤̐̐͆ȅ̵̖̖͓͆̔͘s̸̨̘̥͎̉̈ĕ̴̡̡̲͔̫̾̋̌h̴̨̛̟́͑T“ .debmaerts yrd-shtnom a
,aet teews fo rehctip a htiw semitemoS
,eporuE ni seidaL dna sdroL htiw dezilaicos dah ehS
.flesmih levart ot erised on ot
”?uoy era eman s’doG ni tahW“ ”.uoy knaht I“
,ffo mih tup taht ekil elcatsbo elttil a tel htimS royaM taht dias eb reven ti tel tub ”,waltuo uoy eralced ybereh I“ ”.llew yreV“
,meht derebmemer dniw eht tnaem ti dnA
72‘ fo odanrot kaerf eht litnu
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sehtycs erew ereht ,yhw ,enon dah ohw esoht rof dnA .snug dah ohw
.deniatretne yletavirp dah flesreh ynahteB snalp suoirav gnoma neeb dah emoctuo na hcus ,deednI
:tsiolos a eb ot tnetnoc demees eh ecno roF
hguoht ,tsacrevo emoceb dah evoba seiks eht ,tniop emos tA
’?niyats ot ereht saw tniop tahw‘ dna
” ̵̲̩̲̯̟̘̇̒á̴͖͍̣̉e̶̡̱͉͖̪̮̟͛͌S̷̩̙̼͓̥̝̯̈͑̾̉̑̽e̵̦̞̞͉͓̲̓h̶̲͔̠͝T̷̼̱̥̉́̋͘o̸̦͙̤̼͑́ţ̸̻̜̰̘̍̈̾͆͘͝͠n̴̛̙̝̗͑I̶͖̥̎ĺ̵̬̣͙͓͐̍͊̌͒l̵͍̹̰̬̼̜̿̏̂͑̓̇ͅẠ̶̥̠̿̔̂͑̀͘s̵̢͕̹̩̿̄̎̀̈̀̐r̷̢̥̺̱̻͊̍ȍ̷̳̣̥̋ͅl̶̪͙̜̻͙̒ó̶̻̰̱̫̩̤̹͂̂̈́́͠͝Ć̵̭̹̥̯̆̏͘͝͝s̵͕̫̺͓̏͌͊͘̕͝t̸͈̫̞̭͖̉͜I“ .enola reh dna
,desiar srehtaef s’eiggaM
,nwot a rof hcum ton si derdnuh wef A
,onafreuH siuL dna
.ydaer saw reppus taht dellac aM litnu niamer dluow yeht os dnA
”!eman sih wonk t’nod I“
,nepo gnuh s’ollidamra reh dna htuom reh htob hguoht dnA
,yks eht ot desiar erew seye dna sdnah sih tub
,dniw dloc a mih evoba trid tsal eht dial ehs nehw dna
seirots eseht derebmemer dniw eht dnA
.slliw s’renwo rieht fo tfereb yleritne ylneddus sdnah ni
,secalp yawa raf fo snoitpircsed rof noissap taerg a evah ot demees siuL .rM
,gnidnatsrednu htiw ton
.thgil a-ezalb a otni niar eht snrut
.sehsiw lanif lausunu tahwemos s’htimS ssiM eb ot
̵̙́y̵̠͉̞͗͂e̶̳̝͉̺̫̍̓̅̚͘l̵͈͗͌l̷̝̝̑̒͊͊̓Á̶̤̊̇y̸̲̩̓̓r̸̨̪̀͛͐͋e̶̢̗̭͉̟̚v̸͈̭̠͔͍͒̆͋̌̕Ę̶͓̰̒̃͛͝͝n̷̺͚̝̊̂̀͝w̸̢̲̣͕̾̏̑ǫ̶̨̦̣͚͋͛̎̀D̸̤̦̞̫͋̆̕ė̵͕̖̟̹͚̂̃̀͂B̸̖̰̪̀̈́l̷̨̩͉͎͊̆̅͛l̷͓̮͇̪̔̃͊̕ì̸̹̫̅͝ͅẆ̴̨̛͚͝Ĭ̷̹̼̬̤͍d̴͚͛̌̓n̸̨̩̣̘̦̍̆͂͆͘A“ .gnidnatsrednu ton fo ytuaeb eht fo dna
,ffo erew sthgil eht lla erus edam ehs
,deddon eh neht tuB
,seye s’siuL fo srenroc eht ni gnidnats sraet was ynahteB ”̴̟͋͌o̵̟͈̳̺͍̅̽̐͂G̵̙̭̑̓̍ḍ̸̹́ñ̶̢̗̰͙̈́̚A̷̲̒e̵̜͐́́̔͝r̵͕̹͖̟̈́͛e̶̙̐͌̒H̴̗̃͆̓͝m̵̢̐͆̉o̶̘̲̿͛͌̒r̷̛̟̘̎̃͊͝F̷̻̱̥̱̮̓̋̏ĕ̴͔̱̋͆̚s̶̺̩̣͔̹̉ì̶̖̽͐Ṟ̶̭̇̒͝l̶͖͍̳͍͆̀̎́ļ̴̬̟̝̏͜ḯ̶̧̺̠̘̈́̕͠W̷̧̛̠̍̕I̸̬̹͑͒̚ǹ̶̲o̶̱̘͎̦͐͜ǫ̶̫͖͉͔̎S“ .llew sa
,wonk ot demees ydobon snosaer rof ,dellac saw tahw deniatniam dna ni dediser ohw
’yawa nwolb lla s’ti‘ dna
nagihciM ni erehwemos enummoc tnecajda-rekauq a fo nos dna detacude-egelloc ,drallam ,nnamitliT
,dah yeht tahw tlef dah ohw
,aciremA saw siht tub
,devom ti taht tnaem tI
”!won lleh eht thgir ereh tuo eb ot desops s’eh hctibavunos reve-lleh-eht-tahw ro nam-erujnoc denmad taht dnes uoY“
,ylwols egamad rehtaew nehw nevE .esuoH htimS eht
,tsew denrut yeht rehtaR
.yrellag yrruFoS sih no dna
,nemow ro ,nem ylno eht morf raf erew yeht dna
.rohtua eht yb daer
.rehtegot gnis dluow ynahteB dna siuL netfO ”.hguone doog“
,mih htiw gnis ot dellepmoc si tohsrae nihtiw enoyna
snoitcelloc yrots gnitluser eht fo emoS
.nwo rieht tub yrots yna neeb reven dah ereht dneterp ot
.lla ta gnihton yas dluow yeht netfo tuB
,retal skeew emoS
,esruoc fo ,yad enO
ti rO .’ninthgil htiw edisni pu til lla
,dlot neeb dah yeht seirots eht ,slevart rieht fo seirots eht ,seirtnuoc dlo rieht morf deirrac yeht seirots eht lla
.deraelc yks eht ,deid dniw eht
,hguone ydrahloof ro ,hguone suoiruc nezitic yreve
,sgnis regnarts eht revenehW
.ecnatirehni reh rof rethguad reh ecudes ot gniyrt fo
,dedne gnos eht tnemom ehT
stseug rehto s’siuL
snopaew rieht deraef dah eh naht ,ylraelc ,erom on siht deraef retfird eht tuB
demussa erew tahw fo tsoc eht revoc ot
̸̨̹͉̜̖̳͒͛̌͆ň̶̤͕̙͍̇͛̒̆̈́w̸̥̭̯̘̙̤̱̋̀͛̉̕Ö̷͎̗̤́̕ͅͅI̷̲̺̩͐̇̉̈t̸̨͖̻̗̭̣͆̌a̶͇͈͋̐̌h̷̢͙͎̍̀͋̊͐͠T̷̲͕̹̥͖̪̋͛͝e̵͈̩͌̋͝n̶̢̛̰͔͛̇̈́͛O̵͙̥̔̽̌̿̏̕y̵͔̬̫̝̙͂̈͛̈͂̕̚ḽ̷̢͈͘ͅn̴̮͎͓̓̒̊̒̽̈́ͅÒ̴͈̙̑ȩ̷̜̣̟̤͆̈́̕h̶̞̠͎͚̞͌T̵̬̫̖͍̪͚̓̽̐s̵̳̙̺̿̎̌͊͘ṭ̷̡̤̜̯̂̈͂̊͒I“ thgis rieht fo tuo mih deviecer duolclennuf eht dna
.yawa kool ot elbanu ,ni gninioj
.erom on nwot ni uoy tnaw t’nod yeht“
,nward snug rieht dah gnag sregoR efaR eht fo stnanmer tsal ehT
.deirt eh rohpatem hcae ekil hcum yrev saw ti sey
,uoy dniheb tuhs rood eht gnittel dna
”.doolb erom tub ’nihton htiw deifsitas eb
.tuo siht gniyrrac fo stsoc yna revoc ot desu yenom eht dna
oga sraey beJ deirub dah yeht erehw morf raf ton
”̷̢̼̀̆h̵͇̙̀t̴̟̅͒͒̽ā̶̺͝ẹ̸̢̪͋ͅͅr̵̮̔B̶͐́͜f̵̗͓̋̈͂O̸͓̯͓̩̅͑̈͜t̶̜̝͍͗̋̍́u̷̱̓̑̓O̴̞̯̽̑̚t̸͍̍̇͝l̴̳̀̈ȋ̷̱̲̟͕͚̒̊͌̐ů̷͎̳͔̙̀ͅB̸͇̝̘̖͛̏̌͠e̵̪̋̾ͅḦ̸̥̱́̈̈́̿t̴͎̱̫̎͐̈́a̵̺̩̾͠͝͠ĥ̶͔͕͒́T̵͚̫̉̈̎e̶͕̲̖̻̓̍͌̿͘s̵̨͙̳̰͛̈́ư̵̡̓̈́̇͆ó̵̙͇̤̍̀̎ͅH̸̙̜͂̓́̅̕ë̸̡͙̦͚̆͂̊h̸̘̓̌͘͘͝T̶̫̬̄̆͝s̸̗̝̘̺̋͘͘Ḭ̸̡͖̀͒͒ś̷͍̞̟̱̫̌̔̀͑ȉ̴̦̞̺͖ḧ̸͔̞͈́T“
,deromur si ti ,sregoR efaR
.esimorpmoC iruossiM eht dna ynitseD tsefinaM
.liarT nogerO dlo eht fo etuor derreferp eht gnola
riaffa fo dnik eht t’nsaw ti
?siht ekil dne ot retteb ti t’nsaW ”
,yenruoj siht ekam ot meht ecudni ot ,yleslaf
yllufknaht hcihw ,gnignis fo stsrubtuo suoenatnops fo stroper sa llew sa
’.ecalp detangised susnec‘ a ylerem ot deldniwd dah ti
.etag eht ta reh teem t’ndid siuL
ereht saw esle ohW
,sraey eht revo ,srerednaw dna sretfirD
.noilattab yvan elohw a gnissuc-tuo fo elbapac naht erom dna
?seman rieht erew tahW
:snoitcurtsni rehtruf tcepxe ot ton erew yehT
,ylivaeh gninruhc
,senil citamard yltaen ni teerts niam ytpme na no noon hgih ta rehtohcae decaf nem eht erehw
.snoinapmoc etanutrofnu owt sih dna
” ̴͇̥͆̂́̃̂̀͌l̵̛̛̰̦̟̻̯͎̦̋͋̇̋̽ḽ̶͉͓̳̞̳͐̾̂͘͠a̷͂̐̉͜f̸͎̞̐̈́͑̊͒͂͝n̷̲̬͖̽̏ḭ̴̡̩̗̆̑̏͆͋å̸͎̫̺̂͆Ȓ̴̢̘̲̯̝͂̒͝e̸̖̠̜̔͜h̸̤̩͕̙́̒̽́̉̈̍T̷̡̨͈͍̪̃̍͌͌́͝o̴͐͋̈́̐ͅT̵̝͈̜͓͓̯̝̉̀̊e̷͓̥̐̑̆̋̒c̵̢̘̖͎̯̺̲̔̅̓̌̑̚͠ḁ̵̡̧͚̖̮̠̓͑̔̿F̷̨̮͉̯̤̗̖̃̈́̉́͠y̸̧͎͖̲͍͖̓͗̐M̴̮͇͍̊̐̌̊̓͘͘ͅn̷̦͕̈́r̶̡̡̨̛͙̠̻̫̂̉̑̄u̴̫͇̞̙͐̉̒̊́͠Ť̸̛̹̜̟̭͈̆͝l̸̢̨͕̖͉̼̑̾l̸̡̪̤͕͛͝I“ .mih rof detrap dworc eht ” ̶͈̱̋m̷̨̩̫͎̠̍͑̓̓͜r̶͔͌a̸̩̎̿͌̿̓͠H̵͓̲̦̩̉͐͘ó̴̯̠͖̰̇̓͠N̵̼̾ͅͅĕ̶̱̖̃M̴͙͇͚͍̣̈́͛̒͜͝͝ỏ̸̯͓̱̫̤Ḑ̶̩͚̱̦͋̀l̷̫̺̟̀̈̍l̷͇̫̈́i̵̡̢̞̜̰̣̊̅W̵̡̳̹̲̔̿̐͊͘y̷̤̼͖̦̒ë̵̗͖͚͜h̸̟͂̍͑̉T̴͉͇͒̎̕͜s̵̪̘̟̞̠͍̬͂̽̊̅͑͗͘n̶͍̘̐̆̂̈́͑͌í̷̪̣̬̻̋̉̈́͒͘ͅa̸̧̟̥̗͠Ŕ̷̛͔̘̩̂̾̈́̃͘ę̶͚̣̟̩̝͇̈́͑̊̈́͐h̶̨̗͍͕̘͓̎̎̈̊̿T“
,yrotirreT aksarbeN
lleW“ ”…waltuo na uoy eralced ybereh I
retfird etoyoc sseleman a ,emit tsaL
.taorht reh ni derrits gnihton tuB
.gnignis saw retfird eht sgniht eht gnidnatsrednu
.raey retfa raey denruter
detadiuqil dehsiw ehs
noisserpxe na saw ecaf sih no dna
,yas dluow eh ”,emoh ym evah I“
detcepsus ylsuonimulov dna
:tsuj dna thgir saw ti dneterp pleh ot seirots sevlesmeht gnillet
,erehwon fo elddim eht ni tuo ,denwo ehs esuoh a retne ot meht derewopme dna detcurtsni tI
,eno otni lla meht tup ot detpmetta ehs os
.evitaler era sgniht hcus tuB
.eton sseldrow ,elgnis a gnas eh dna
,ssenneknurd fo tuob gnol s’keew a retfa ,ssibroC eteP
.dnuos nettogrof tsomla tub railimaf-gnol emos ecnatsid taerg a ta gniraeh fi sa
̵̣̙͈̟̂̽́͑̑ḁ̸͈͕̬͇͆̔̂͑͌̅̚͜l̷̡̝͍̺͖͌̓͜l̴͕͙̊͐̋͠ě̸̠̹ŗ̷̩͔̭̖͝b̴̧̡̨̬̮̰̂̉̈̾̑m̸̳͙͈̫̘͐͋̍̌̕̕U̷̖͎̠͙̣̱̫͂ṛ̴̨̻͉̿̋̋͛ŭ̷̢̯͇̹͙͇̄͠ó̷̥̫̩̠̮Y̴̩̞͎̳͗̐͐d̵̫̃ë̷̬̹̹̲́̽̅͛̐̐̔͜ͅe̵͕͐͑̉͜͜Ǹ̶̡͈̈ẗ̶̢͇͈̤̹͈́̈̿̚o̵̧̹̖͇̪͕̔͐Ñ̸̝͖̼͖͖̓l̵̲̲̯͎͚̭͗̅͗l̶̥̟̞̟̰͋̃̈́̑͑̚͜͝ḯ̶͕̦̦̦W̵̢̰̫̥̘͂̈́̊̀̆̌͘Ḯ̶͙͍̘̯̭͕͇̿͊͑ḑ̴̦̗͓̠͕͂̋͗̌̾n̶̹͙̻̆͒̔͘̕͜A“ .draeh reve dah ynahteB gniht lufituaeb tsom eht saw tI
.ti fo draeh ton evah I neht
,derebmemer ti ,togrof klof latrom nehw ,dlot selat eht lla taht tnaem tI
:mus elbanosaer a rof dlos etatse laer ehT
.hcrop eht no t’nsaw eH
,ssibroC fo sekil eht yb enodtuo eb ot ton ,demialced htimS royaM
yenruoj gnol a morf emoh gnimoc ekil tlef dah ti dias siuL nehw saw
,sedaced eht revo ni nekat dah siuL sretfird eht lla fo gnitirwdnah eht ni ,s’siuL ni ,gnitirwdnah reh ni ,yrarbil eht ni skoob eht
detaitnatsbus reven erew
.elddup a ssorca pets ot gnilbis denethgirf a gnigaruocne
,serutcurts desunu eht fo tser eht nwod erot
,smees ti ,retfird ehT
.rehtona eno ot kaeps naht rehtar teerts niam ssorc snoitcaf owt eht dehctaw ynahteB ,keew a ot hgin roF
,eton reh ni gnos eht draeh eh
,esraoh saw repsihw s’ynahteB ”.potS“
.esroh sih morf nellaf secnaraeppa lla yb
” ̶̧̥̬͇̼͇̆̀̎͌̆͗n̶̡̖̦̲̯͔̥̓̓m̴̡͙̓͆̀͘͝u̸͗̈͛͗͜t̸̻̟͚̬͚̠͌̿u̶̫̘̟̲͔̼͓̓̔A̷̳̹͌̔̑̉̏͝ḙ̷̉m̵̢̭̝̹͖̓̈̉̆̏̌o̸̡͕̝̥̣͐S̶̮͙͖̻͍̤̈́̈́͜f̸̥͙̾̐̀̅̓̄Ọ̴̪́d̸̜̗̮͉̗̼̣̾̀̾͛̾͘n̷̢̪̟̞̔̌͛̓̈̈͝E̵͚̘̼̍̔ĕ̷̡̡̽̅̇̒͜h̴͊͑̊͛̋̚͝ͅT̷̟͕͕̥̾̋͋̅̾̋̕ţ̸͍̈́̔͂͌Ä̸̫͕́e̸̡̙͝b̵̢̜͎͖̻̑̀̔͂̑͛͠y̸̢̪̦͔͙͖̜͆͛̏̿̎a̸̢̿͠Ḿ̸͙̟͌͆̚͠ḍ̴̙̞̌̈́̄̇ṇ̶̲̤̲̩́̆́̃͐͘A“ .raef ot wenk dna
,nehctik eht ni mih dnuof ehS
,ylneddus ’nikaw ekil tlef
”̸̱̪͔̱̽̃̃̕ṅ̵̛͓̫͕̮̩̜̺̔̍̎͝ẁ̸̫̙̣̞̱̤̩ơ̸̡͎͕̦̼̒̾T̵͈̘̯̭̊̅̋͂ņ̸͖̘̣̆̒͆͛̓͌͠ͅẻ̵̢̳̖̟̣͜ẗ̷̠̏͗̀̆̐͌t̸̨̢̠̫͈͈̘̽̌͆̏̕o̵̭̊̽͘ğ̶̼̭̪́͐̕͘͝ȑ̷͙̏̓̓̌͝ő̸̢̳̻͌͌̿͂̓̈́F̶̥̦̹̦̺̌͐y̶̲̥̯̘͎̓̎̿̇̅̕ͅͅr̸̨̫̫̫̦̳̞̓̽̏e̴̺͚͋̿̌̋̒̈́͝v̵̲̀̅͐̈́̾̋͘Ę̶͉͕̠̼̼͌ṅ̸̮͕̺̘͇̟̽̆̒͆͜I“ .ynomrah a ni strap rof ytnuob suomrone na si ti tub
,flesti gnidliub eht fo noitilomed eht tub ecalp eht ot enod eb dluoc gnihtyna erofeb tsrub elbbub siht hguoht
.ytiretsop rof meht evreserp tseb ,tnemgduj rieht ni ,dluow yaw revetahw ni etanimessid dna ,dnib ,tnirp ot erew yeht esehT
,sniatnuom debmilc dah ehS
.sedaced eht revo tekciht a otni flesti gnimrofsnart ylisub dna yllaudarg
,gnos eht dootsrednu ehs woh
,yretsym a deniamer spotfoor eht morf dednecsed dah eh woh dna nehW
.teerts niam fo elddim eht otni dna spets noolas eht nwod ylwols dessecorp retfird ehT ”
.hO -fi pots ot elba eb d’yeht yllufepoH
,gnihtemos fo ssam looc taerg a tnaem tI
,elleb nwot eht
,noonretfa eht ni rebrab eht tfel eh sa
,aksarbeN fo ytisrevinU eht ot ro
,ksa ot snoitseuq dnasuoht a dah ynahteB
,ti hguorht was dniw eht tuB
.elihw eht lla ,ekilrehcaerp
ssibroC eteP ruoS dna htimS royaM htob ot flesmih gnitneserp eb ot deromur saw
,pots dluoc ehs taht wenk ynahteB tnatsni emas eht nI
̶̯͇͇̯̞̞̌́̕͝g̵̛̣̮̫̼͖͓̍̑́̆̈͜n̴̝͍̳̽͆̈́́ï̶̛̖̱̲̹̠̌͂͂p̴̨̧̝̼͇͈͗̉͊̐͜é̸͎̙̈́͒e̴̙̠̞̝͖̝̣͋t̸̩͒̀̓͠S̶̡̢̲̩̯͒͌̅d̵̖̓̽͒̆̈͜n̸̡̼̫̼̈́̀̽͑Â̷̢̭̥̬̆̓̔ģ̶̺͖̱͂͋̐n̶̤̗̙̩̲̿i̴̟̠̪̰͛͊̾̽̕t̵̢̮͕̫̰̭̬̓̂́̊̐͝͝t̴̨̧̤̱̩̝̱͊͗̎̋ẻ̴͖̞͘S̶̺͌ẹ̸̱̮̘̰̘̪͝Ḃ̷͉̥̜͝l̸̨̤͚̳̟̈́̈́̓̌͌̏̇l̶̩͙͈̲̒̉͛̎̓͘į̴̡͓̯̪͙̤̃̅̒͒̊̓̈́Ẁ̵̨̨̞̣̣̭̘̑͒̃̄͝ņ̸̘̥̎͊͐͆ṵ̸̧̰̲͓̜̀Š̴̨̘̪̻̳̟̺̍̏̇͘͝e̶̞̜̜̜͎̞̯̽̑̆̕h̵̡̗͓̘̳́̉̈̉Ť̶̡̤̦̝͕̱̖̀è̵̢̡̛͕̼̖͉͈̃̓̉͝͝r̶̫̮̀̐̂̏̒͠ͅe̴̡̛̛͖̬̿͒͆̓h̶̯̺̞̰̳̩͝W“ .tnahpmuirt erom eht
,palfgniw yreve ,tsug yreve ,noitom yreve taht
,gnidnatsrednu fo kcal rieht fo gnidnatsrednu tub
,erifssorc eht ni mih hctac dna ereht tuo kaerb gnitoohs eht tsel ,hcnar s’ssibroC ta knub sih ot gninruter morf neddibrof dah ehs mohw
.eneres saw ecaf siH
ynomrah evitiutniretnuoc dna egnarts emos tih ehs llit hctip ni detsujda gnas eiggaM eton eht dna ,taht neht
,aksarbeN fo etatS eht ot yrotirreT aksarbeN morf detaudarg doots ti hcihw no dnal eht emit eht yb taht espalloc noitalupop a hcus decneirepxe tdleftatS fo nwot eht ,tcaf nI
.reverof tsal ot gniog reven erew sgniht esohT
,neht woN“ .demra eb ot
.skramer lacipyt eht fo evitatneserper erew
”,tdleftatS fo elpoep eht yb em ni detsev ytirohtua eht yb
.sthgil nrehtron eht ees ot elcric citcra eht ot dekkert ,snaeco dessorc
,yaw siht elttil a daeh sih detliT .deddon retfird ehT
”̷̡̼̰͚̤͛̔̉̕͠r̶̨͇͍͙͂ǫ̸̩̼͙͒o̶̙̟͎͛̀̑́̍D̶̡͚̦͉̄͜e̶͕̺̖̕͝ḥ̶̭̤̍T̷̬̪̅e̶̬͓̼̔d̸̮͔́ȋ̸̦̂̚s̴̝̥͎̺͒͌͜t̸̳̜͉̰͍̓͊̈́͋̽ú̴͔̟̿O̷̡̟͎̱͊̎͆ͅt̴͎̭̺͚̐f̷͇̻̺̒é̸̫̺̭̹̂̈̀͝Ĺ̶͇̪͚͎͜s̴̞̖͆̎̋̐͝e̷̮͖̹͒ö̵̢̱̗̪͖́͆̆͝ḧ̸̨̧̫̔̾S̶̰͊̓͒̅̎ͅs̷̡͕̮̱̰̓͗̒̌̚i̸͚̙͖̺͐̉̊H̶̻͔̣͖̹̾̚ê̷̺͇̹͈͝r̵̫̫̮̪̓̓͠ͅè̴͓͙̑W̴̢͔͐͋͑ê̴͉̙̝͐͗s̷̰͛͐̑͂ō̸͉͇͝h̵̪̲̫͕̬̒͆͌̓T“
dna nrettap nmelos nwo sti otni evow ti taht
,detraped srehto dna
”?neht ,flesym denialpxe I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,wenk ehs taht lla fo
,namstocs a ton saw eh taht saw
”.uoy ot flesym nialpxe ot deen on evah I“
.t’ndluow ehs taht dna
,retfird eht sa eton emas eht gnimmuh nageb dna
,niar tfos dna rohcirtep gnitacixotni htiw seiks eht pu denepo dna
,tsewhtron yb tsew nrut reh nees evah dluoW
,htimS .srM dna royaM
,tnatropmi tsom eht saw hcihw aedi on dna
,erots lareneg eht pota nettog wohemos dah
.gniod deen thgim sdeed lufwalnu revetahw od ot gnilliw sa
.dewollof siuL dna ynahteB
.tnemal a dna yballul a strap lauqe dednuos tI
.selas koob dnah-dnoces ro ,srelaed koob erar
?tnenitnoc elohw a sfrawd duolcrednuht a fo ezis eht ekil ecneirepxe roirp ruoy defrawd hcihw
.fo draehnu ton erew sgniht hcuS
ynahteB dna siuL
.noisnapxe erom yfitsuj ot meht tuoba pu gnikam won neve erew srehto taht seirots eht
,llew sa gnas nemnug sih dna kcaJ namstocS dna nnamitliT
̷̢̨̦̱̻̺̒̑̒͌̑͘r̵͉̼̔͑͐e̸͍͍̝͉͐̆͌́͛̑̇m̵̗̪̿̃̋͒̊̓̉m̷̡̡͎̥̗͚̃̈͆̃̔̓u̷͍̲̣̿̾͘͜S̶̛̰͈̖͕̦̫̞͐̂̍̚͠͝ḙ̶͇̙̙͗̉̈́͝ͅḩ̷̢̗͍̤͍̉̀͊̔̔Ţ̴̪̫̯̉̒̿̐ͅǫ̴̨͕̺̖̼͖́T̵̡̫͖͎̼̿͆͐e̵̯̱̹̙̪͕̒̋̅͘y̵̡̮̙̭͕̖̖̿̏̚b̸̫̈́̈́̅̎d̸͕̩͍̝̫̏̌o̴͓̜͔̘̓͠o̸̮̙̐̍̿̋̂͜G̵͕̞͍͎̬̰̈́̋͗̚y̸̧̛͈̮͛͌́̏̓a̷͇̞͖̋̄̏̓S̶͎̳͈̙̼̉̋͂̇̓̓͜͝ͅl̶̙͙̣̑̓ͅl̴̛̺͎͚̔̽͛̈́͝I“ .reverof tsal ot gniog reven saw ehS
,snialp eht ssorca ,rednuht tnatsid fo dnuos eht emac ereht htrae yrd fo sluflevohs eht neewteB
,sroyevrus eht no kcehc ot tuo gnidir fo daetsni ,hcnar ssibroC eht ot gninruter fo daetsnI
.revocer ton did ,detciderp sa ,sregoR efaR  2 fo 2 traP
.ti rof yap dluoc uoy sa gnol os
.emoh a yllanif dah eh taht yas dna
.dessap evah sniar eht retfa ssenllits tnelis looc eht ekil
”̸̳̥̲͖́̏͛̾e̶̟̜̲͆̊r̶̮̳͉͂́̐o̷̜͖͋̃̓͆ͅm̷̪̙̠̿̇͒̒ý̸̰̣̼̾̽͆n̶̨̩̠̦̓̑̐̿͐A“ .rehtegot toN
rehto eht taht noicipsus ni hcae
.ti fo ssam eritne eht dehsup ro
̸͕̞͙̣͌͐̆̒̎e̶̪̟̣̪̫̒̓s̴̭̐͊̆ī̸̻̣̱̣̠̂̅r̶̙̘̼͖̳̾̑̓̉n̸͍͕̼̞̑͋ͅu̵̺̫͠S̴͚̗̄̅͆͗ȩ̶̻͕̮̦̃̑̔̇͌h̷̢̗̹̩̾̑̒̀T̴͉͊n̷̙̓̾̓̚I̶̢̢̫̗̽͘t̶̢͇͚̤̏̈u̵̯̥͙̤͋͗̿̈̆ͅO̶̮͂̏̄͒͒e̶̙̩̭̽̃͒ͅB̵̻̩̖͍̾̔͝ļ̷̱̠̯̃͋̈́̕l̶̩̓͝i̸̠͚̱̺͙͌̐͝͝Ẃ̴̞͕̳̺̆Į̷̒̄̅̚͜͝ŏ̵̤͔̝̗S“ ”.lleweraf yas su tel nehT“
,htimS ynahteB fo sevil eht ni dna
,lufyoj erom eht sthgieh detuohs sti edam ylno hcihw
,noitamitse reh ni ,erew ohw
,tnorf tuo eert mulp eht htaeneb mih deirub ehS
,dessap dah ti nehW
,repsihw retfird eht raeh ot hguone raen seno ylno eht erew—
otni tup erew yeht tnemom eht rof
.dnal eht revo gnirevoh
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,hguorht ’nikaerb nus eht dna“ ,cisum elbaffeni eht nihtiw tpar neeb gnivah fo gnileef eht ebircsed ot yrt netfo dluow siuL
,srenruom rehto yna neeb dah ereht fI
.mih detroppus srumrum yrgna fo surohc A
.tnias gnivil a deredisnoc ylfeirb saw eh erehw
.sregoR efaR fo taht ekil esac rehtruf on decudorp dna
erofeb dnas yrd ot denrut dah ti fi sa
,hcrop noolas sih no saw taog ehT
.niaga tdleftatS ni toof gnittes reven dna dlrow eht fo srednow eht lla gniees
niereht dnuof eb ot ytreporp rehto lla dna
.spotfoor eht morf eciov a tuo gnar
.esruoc fo ,rehcnar eht ediseb saw htimS royaM
”ydnaD“ hplodnaR
,si eh tahw deedni dna
,ainrofilaC drawot ecirava eht
.teef sih ot ylmlac nettog dah retfird eht ,nihtiw
”?tnaw uoy od lleh eht tahw dna“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
,yas retfird eht raeh ot emit ni devirra ynahteB — .ton did ti tuB
.noziroh eht gnissorc enil llauqs a ekil dewollib ,srood eht drawot edorts eh sa ,ohcnop siH ”.enod evah I
,derusaert ti taht worros a saw ti tub
,tsap eht ni ,syawlA
.esruoc s’retfird eht spahrep ro
dnuof eb ot syawla erew deb dna laem toh a erehw
”!?em ot flesrey nialpxe ton ot deen yna tog uoy“
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”,pu ’ninepo sduolc eht ekil tlef tI“ .enola netfo tub
.hgual a htiw dauqs gnirif eht gnicaf srytram rof tif noitcidelav a dna nmyh lanoissecer a
,ediw seye ,pu srae
,noziroh raf eht no mrotsrednuht taerg a ’niees ’na llih a no ’nidnats ekil tlef tI
,sgniht tnereffid deedni erew esoht fi ,spahrep ,tirips ro ria
.eman s’regnarts eht wenk
,ezeeuqs dna wap s’ollidamra eht ekat dluow mussop ehT
,kcalb dna kciht erew daehrevo sduolc eht won tuB ”
,mlac tsomtu htiw denialpxe retfird eht tub
taht seye sih ni was ehS
.esruoc fo ,dnuorg eht tih ti nehw degrahcsid eno a toN
nwod doolf hsalf a ekil teerts niam nwod dellor ,gnos ni desiar ,eciov siH
,nogerO drawot deirrac sepoh eht ,ereh dessorc taht sliart eht delevart dah ohw elpoep eht fo seirots eht tnaem taht dna ”̶̥̙̲̘̩̓h̵̢̖̜͒̈́̈́̃͝ť̵̗̥̈́͝á̸͔̫̞͈̭̅͘é̴̦̩̞Ḑ̶̳̳̃̓ͅś̴̛̹̻̲͕́̀A̸̝̮̅̑̊́p̷̠͇̺̗̈́ē̵̻̲̝̩̂͝e̴̱͌͝D̷̞͇͊͂̎ͅs̷̮͖͑͌̋͘A̶̫̿p̷͙̀͌̉ḝ̴̡̜͎̯̌e̶̢͚̔̋̋͝l̴̦͐̑͂͋s̶͓̳͚̒͐̆̈́A“ .llew sa derebmemer ti ytislaf esohw
.flesmih rof regral eno dna
,retfird eht rof nobruob a deruop taog ehT
” ̶̠̭͂̑̀r̵̰̩̻̜̤̯̓͐̌̕͘͜ę̷̛͎́̽̓w̵̝̐ś̶̰̼̜̺̈͠ñ̶̲̼̉͊͝A̴͓̪͓̒̍͌̊́̚̚ẏ̶̢̮̘̳̞̋̀͛̓͂M̴̢̉͋̀̅̆s̴̡̊͌Ȉ̵̥̝̬̻ď̸̰̅̀͂ǐ̴̩̺̈́̄̍̅̽a̵̗͐̐̆͛̎r̸̦͓̬͓͈̞̓̉̀̏͘͜f̴̡͖̫́̈̔́́́Ả̶̢͓̝̹m̷̥̀̋͘̚I̸͓̓̇͂͆͐̈́̏t̵͈̟̩̱̯̏̂ͅā̷̛̬̭͙͚̥͚h̵̜̏̓̈̂̇̀̔T̴̬̞͆͌͌́̄͛͝d̵̨̜͖̘̯̱̰͂̈́͆͆̓̌͝n̷̛̼͚̭̹͂͆͛̈́ͅA“ .dnuorg eht dehcuot regnol on teef siH
daehrevo pu denepo duolclennuf eht nehW ”
,sseug a derutnev siuL ”,ris ,kniht I“
,enO yloH ,eM ni gniS“
.ssucsid ot hcum dah lla
.tseugesuoh s’htimS eht sa gniyats ollidamra eht ot ecnatsiser elttil ylgnisirprus pu tup dah aM
,rof ereh emac I taht lla
.meht fo yna sa ylitraeh sa gnignis
”,gnignis neeb evah I
’,esoprup sti devres d’nwot
.rethgiarts elttil a pu tas retfird ehT
dedoolf erew secaf sa nettogrof deppord snopaew ”
.mih retfa ni trebelgnE coD degdun yadakceH
.egaugnal sih fo ssenluof eht htiw denrecnocnu yllohw ecno rof
,neht tuB .gnilttesnu ma I
?ecnereffid a saw ereht fi yas ehs dluoc woH
gnag eht fo pihsredael ekat ot tnaem
,mlac elbadaernu ylno saw edis rehto eht nO
,htimS ynahteB ssiM A
.dehtooms yeht gnignisnu yldetcepxenu deniamer oot ehs nehw tub
,klaw ot nageb yeht ,drow rehtruf a tuohtiw tuB
,rehtona eno edisgnola peels dna thgif ot tnetnoc neeb dah
,worc eht ot denrut seye s’retfird ehT
,renroc hcrop eht ta ,revewoh ,yadakceH eiggaM .srM tuB
.noolas eht otni deklaw eh ,derrucco dah yranidroartxe revetahw gnihton fi sA
.ti gniyas detsiser reh ni gnihton tub
ebircsed ot elbanu flesreh dnif dluow ynahteB ,sraey retal nI
,won ereh saw ehs tuB ”
,hcram a eb ot dliw oot saw tI
.snoitadnuof eht tub gnihton dniheb gnivael
,floWcaM boR yb
”.ti ees ot dlrow elohw’t ni ekawa nosrep ylno eht s’uoy ’niwonk dna ,elap og yks tsae eht ta nikool ,thgin eht atni tuo niklaw dna
,tnemelffab dna ,raef saw ereht edis eno eht nO
yreV“ .tnemom a rof tnelis saw noolas ehT
,tnediser tnenamrep eno ylno saw ereht ,ytsenoh lla nI
,ereh saw ehs elihw dna
.hguone elbanosaer si tahT“
,tsae epoletna eht
.deliaf yleritne dah
.tsirw reh no ylevixelfer hcnelc dnah s’siuL tlef ynahteB
ytniatrec htiw dias eb dluoc taht gniht ylno eht tsap esohw tuoba olaffub a ,kcaJ namstocS
,ti ees ot ereh yeht erew neve
seirots eseht derebmemer dniw eht dnA
,won sraey ynam woh
,taht ecaf reh no kool a
.ti sserpxe ylluf ot
,esirnus erofeb ruoh na
,trebelgnE coD ot noitativni fo don s’eiggaM
’onafreuH eiuoL taht‘
,egassaP tsewhtroN eht dna odaroD lE
,ssensseldeen sti fo
.gnihtyreve nees dna erehwyreve neeb dah ehs seirots reh yb egduj oT
neerg fo edahs a enog dah meht fo segde eht dnuora thgil eht dna
,muh suoituac sih dna
,secalp hcus dehcaer reve ehs rehtehW
.gnignis eht detpurretni evah dluow tahT
:noitidnoc doog ni tpek emoh sih
,htron kcaJ ,htuos tnew nnamitliT
.rettam gnisserp tsom eht sa
,gnidliub eht dezar yleritne
tneiciffus naht erom elttil a erew ,tsael ta ,elas eht fo sdeecorp ehT
sgniht fo skool eht yb rof
smialc ehs sa doog sa si gniraeh reh fi yadakceH .srM spahrep—
sreh pota wap rehto sih ecalp dluow eh dna
tdleftatS fo noitalupop eht dna retfird ehT
.sselehtenon seirots eht lla derebmemer dna
esoht dedesrepus noos gnag remrof s’terref eht gnoma snoisnet tuB
.sniatnuom naht regraL .noitazilivic naht redlO
:wolla dluow tuoyal nwot eht sa meht ot raen sa ro snoitcerid lanidrac ni
,sevihcra ,snoitcelloc ,seirarbil rehto suoirav ot desrepsid saw deniamer tahw fo emos dna
.evila ylduorp ,yltnaifed dna
,meht ediseb ssarg eht gnipporc yllacidohtem beJ htiw semitemos
.retsloh a hcuot ot dnah tsrif eht rof yltnetni gnihctaw
,meht fo snoitareneg nopu snoitareneg ,ecno
.ainigriV ni nik s’efiw ydal sih gnoma tnemeriter a ot tsae kcab enog dna
,llet dluoc eh dehsiw eh yrots eht ,gnimmuh saw eh eton eht ni ,draeh ehS
,erehwemos ereht tuo saw ehs elihw ,enog d’eH
,mih tcetorp dluow retlehs taht ytniatrec eht rednu edisni niamer ot noitanimreted desserpxe sih etipsed
,demees ti ,ydoboN
rehtorb redlo na ekil erutseg a ni ,dnah a tuo dleh eH
.tsixe tonnac raw hcihw tuohtiw tub raw naht redlo tirips emos ro ,ti ni tirips laitram emos ,ti ot taerht emos saw erehT
.kool elbadaernu ,gnol a mih ediseb mussop eht dna ollidamra eht evag etoyoc ehT ”.ris
,riohc tsidohteM lanoitaN naidanaC eht htiw gnus dna
?noitseuq a hcus rewsna ot ynahteB saw htrae no woh dnA
naiffur derih lacol ,sregoR efaR fo esac eht ni sa—htiw semitemos
.erif nmutua na revo yrots tsohg a saw ti ,mrots a dima rethgual saw tI
.nward ydaerla snug
,teerts eht ni tuo dewolleb ssibroC eteP ruoS ”!trebelgnE coD“ — .ot deen on dah ehs taht etanutrof saw ti spahrep oS
yojne esaelP  .nwonknu sniamer
,onafreuH siuL .rM a
secaf eht ssorca deltserw ewa deifirret dna yoj suorutpaR ”̷͓̙̾̀͋͜͝y̷̪̠̯̾̂̇͋̾ḏ̶̼̤͌̽ö̶̳̟́B̷̬͊̽̈̈͜s̴̟̣̦̑̿í̴̮̞͈H̶̛̠͔̺s̴͚̲̳̙͖̎̽̚I̵̗͓͌s̶̪̜̩͚̣̐͊i̷͎̯͉͐h̴͔̉T“ .tnelis ylinots saw
,enod erew sisirc lapicinum fo srettam nehw teY
.yas dluoc illengA ron kenareB rehtien
.dnah sih ni puc eht fo mottob eht ta
”eM hguorhT dna ,enO yloH ,eM ni gniS“
.siuL dna reh rof ecalp a ereht saw erutuf taht ni erehwoN ”̵̡̧͔͉̔t̵͍͆h̶̭͉͓͚̯̏̍̕͠g̴̢̥̣͍͋̿ĭ̷͎l̸͓͚̳͙̏̇n̴̻̈́̏ủ̵͉̰͗̇͘S̴̟̅̃́͗ẽ̷̥̬͍̬̘̀̒h̴͓͖̱̋Ṭ̷̺̞̍́̈̍ṛ̸͙̎͋̅͐͐ǻ̶̛̖̖̹̏͝ė̶̙̺͔͎͇F̵͙͉̜̂͐t̷̨̲̎̉͝n̷̢͓̪͖͓̆͊́͝o̵͉̺͚̽͒́̃̂W̷̧͔̳̔̇̈͝Ȉ̸̢̼̲o̵̥̰̹͕̣͛̿͝N“ .ti fo yrots eht rebmemer
,derebmemer dniw eht taht seirotS
,htaerb peed a koot
dluow dniw eht dnA .elag ydaets a
rebmemer dluoc ynahteB sa raf sa
.og ot desoppus erew yeht woh ot kcab sgniht denrut evah tey yam tahT
,elbisneherpmocni si gnis yeht tahw hguoht neve
”eM hguorhT dna ,enO yloH ,eM ni gniS“
,dellortnoc eb dluoc ytisomina sih nehw ssibroC eteP ,trebelgnE coD
,enog dah liarT nogerO eht ecno taht noitcerid eht
”̴͖͓͔̓̿́́̀s̸̨̟̭̹̰͋͋̆͝d̸̨̮̭͉̺͒̀̄͠͠d̴͔͎̹̝͋̃͝Ọ̵̙̬͕́̈́͂̄̿e̷͍̠̋̀̊̀̾h̷̥̟̒͛T̵̡͍̪̹͇͗ẻ̸̪͝r̷̙̥͖̲̒́͛́͠Å̴̜̖͕̦̳t̵̘͕̹͔̅̂ͅā̶̢̨̫̖̚h̴̖̳̝̄̂̒͘W̵̭̤͙̹͘ḿ̷̡̫̩̭̻͑͐̅͝í̷̢̪̑H̵̳͗̽̽̇̆r̷̢͖̺̘͈̅̆ä̶̇̑ͅę̷͓̖̾H̵͍̯̜̎̾̉̓ỵ̶͖̹͔̐ȇ̴̤̂͆͜h̸͓̥͝T̷̥̿̂͘ͅd̶̞͍̜͖̈́̏͒ͅi̸̡̻͔̺͗̆̄̓͠Ḑ̶̩̝̟͙̆ĕ̶͉̜͔̘͌̅̓r̶̥̘̆̓͑̿̕͜e̴̜̤͒̽͜H̷̦͚̤̒͘ș̷͆̎̏d̵̢̨̝͊̋͝ō̸̖̗̗̞̮̇͆̚Ǵ̷͉̘̱̱f̴̳̹̫͍̳̾́̾̊O̴͚͊d̸̫͊̅r̵̡̦̩̟̒͊͋͗͂ȁ̴̟̮͙̼͍̍̄͝e̷͇̪̹͇̽͝͝ḧ̴͖̳͍̖̀̌n̶̬̻̖̰̽̃U̵͚̽͆ö̴̞́̔̎T̴̛̛̲͈̀̈͊r̸̝͉̹̯̉͗a̴̠̍̄͗̈́t̵͔̂ĺ̸̤͖̫́̓͛̾Ḁ̵̰̺̐̎͆ș̴̡̩͈̈̒̕͜i̴̖͉̎͗Ḫ̵̍̆̒s̴̻̑̾̏̈́͝I̴͖̱͒͛s̷̡̨͖̍̄̃i̵̹̻̟̅h̶͎̱͔̃̕T“
”?yeksihw a tnaw …uoY“
deergasid yeht hcihw no noisacco ylno ehT
,no dnalmraf ni moob evitaluceps ronim a saw ereht
,nepo welb srood eht nehw psag a htiw ylprahs kcab dellup tub
.did hcum yrev ohw esoht erew ereht tuB
.evah uoy tahw si yeksihw fI“
”!nwonknu snosrep ro nosrep“
,deton ynahteB ,trebelgnE coD
.htimS ynahteB ssim a ,srieht fo tneilc emit-gnol cirtnecce na morf
t’now’t ,pu s’doolb rieht nehw sseug I tub“
,stnaw etoyoc siht tahW
niats a ot deird eeffoc
,htlaeh gniliaf gnitic
,ereh devil dah ohw elpoep fo sraey fo sdnasuoht eht tnaem taht dna ”̵̛̛̼̙̃̑͝ẖ̴̘͒̂̀̓͘t̴̲̳̮͛̀a̶̮̎͌ẹ̷̠̦̘͑̐r̸̼͖̳̹̈͌̅̿B̴͕̱̦̝̮̂͌͒͘s̶͈̯̫̱̬̒ḯ̸̧͛̽̚Ḫ̷̲̘̋̉̔̈́ͅn̶̪͉͓͚̫̈́́á̴̞̘̹́ḧ̷̨̢̟́̈T̷͙̳̗̞̲͒̊̃͗̄r̶̨̤͚̣͒̈́̓̉͠ȩ̷̟͓͚̋͆̂̈̓ẗ̸̞͓̥̬͂̐̕͠f̵̝̻̿̐͝o̷̧̪̺̾̄̕Ș̴̨̝͌ę̶̛̿̊̋͝ͅr̵̩̘̐͆̆̏A“ .htaenrednu ynomrah gnitfihs yltbus ylwols eht demmuh ylerem mih htiw moor eht ni meht fo ruof eht
,nwot reitnorf dekcarw-duef a ni deraeppa
.thgirla lla saw ti dna
̴͇̖̐͑͋m̴̜͓̬͉̫̍̔̈̓r̷̜̪̦̹͙͆̐͊͛̒̇̽à̶̡͍̝̏̽́W̷͖̳̗̜͕̺͕̑̂̑͠ę̷̬͚̠̗̯͋͋̃M̵̙͉̂̂̓͐̚͝h̷̬̀̔͗t̶̗̤̲̄̆̅̇e̸͚̎̈̄͘͠p̴̭̃̏̃̕̚é̷̟̰e̴̢͕̊̏K̵̛̪̔͐͗̒̂t̶̺̾̋̂̋͘͘ͅI̷̥̜̞̫̎͒l̷̼̀͌l̴͚̰̭͔̾̍̆̈͗ͅa̷͍̝̭͍͚͇̒͜f̴͈̽͠n̸̪̱̹͓̋̀̈́̍͜i̶̼̬̟̝̥̔͐̈̐̈́̀́͜͜ä̸̝͙̞̬̤́̓͛̂̈́̉̉Ŕ̸͈̄̊ę̸̢͙̟̣̓͂́̈́͂̚ḩ̷̢̺̟͓̫͓̓Ţ̷̈́͊̈́ḋ̵̬͈̹̝̀̽͊̏n̴̨̲̬͍̘̪̱̍̈́̄͋A“ .gninrom siht lla raelc dna ynnus neeb dah rehtaew eht
.mih tneverp ot denimreted saw
.hcrop tnorf eht morf mrotsrednuht eht dehctaw ynahteB
,esruoc sti gnola ,gnitsisernu ,reh gard ti tel ehS ”̶̻̩̭̀y̸̘̮̮̔l̵̘̠̉̍̾̿̄s̷̨͇̙̠͛͛͐ͅu̴̧̺̰̓o̵̦̝͖̪̜̿̇͘ṁ̸̲̩̰͎͜u̸̡̗͋͊̑̃̎h̵͕̭̃t̸͕̰̮́̎̿́̚s̵̨̛̩̀̕o̸̥͖̾Ṗ̴̡̹͙̇͋͊͘y̷̢̨͕̦͗̿͘d̸͚͙͕̕̚ǒ̴ͅb̷͖̣̟̣̜̍̔̐̚͝ẹ̴̦̝͛̂͝͝ṁ̵̡̢̟̯͜o̸̻̟͍͆͆̇͑S̴̨͔̺̞͖̒̋̌y̷͉͎̮͑̃̆B̴̢̡̮͇͌̊́̋d̶̡̧͎̔̿͌̆ͅë̶̡͈̹̭͜͝ṿ̶̀͊͘i̷̥̗̙̽́̀̅͝ẻ̴̞̥͉̥͐́́c̶̙̖͑͘ę̵͉̼̪͗͝ͅR̵͓̘̐ȅ̸̠͠B̵͓͖͖̤͉̑̓͝ỏ̴̘͓̖̲̼̈́̈́͋̌T̶̯̟̠̀͂̚ͅt̶͈̠͛̊̾ͅņ̶̒a̶̢̪̱͎͋̕͠e̴̖̙͓̐ͅM̷̢͔̼̈s̸̿̿̚͝ͅp̶̱̫͍͔̠͋͋a̸̩͉̭̙͑h̷̗̟̜̃̍͠ŕ̵̹̖̺͚̼e̴̛̩͂́P̷̡̺͓̲͜͝ȩ̴̜̤́̈́́g̵̭̘̀͜͜ả̴̲̫̟͉̒̀s̶̰̦̪̘̩͗́͐̽͝s̸̢̭̱̒̆̎̕͝ě̷̫̜͎̮͔̄M̸̢̜͉͇̆̅A̴͓̞̮͐͊̾̃͜ͅs̵͚͂̒̕I̸̤̲͂͗͊š̵̤̺̄̓̿̕i̸͍̇͋h̶̞̔̃͘T“ .tsal eht morf ,deton ynahteB ,tnereffid saw gnos siht ”̵̫̲̫̠̬̍͐̕e̵͎͊ḍ̴͉̖͐͊̎̀i̴̪͊̐̅̊̚ş̴̩̞̀t̷̰͉̠̅ǘ̸͙̬̋̊O̸̗̥̥̓͒̉͒̍ǵ̷͈̙͉̓͒͘̚n̵̘̲̜̿̍̿̚i̶̯͂̈́́l̶̢̬̤̰̏͜t̶̗̋͑̈́̉s̸̤̮̣͔͗́i̷̡̢͐̽͐̕h̷̨͓̿̓Ŵ̵͈͆͊͗Ä̸͓́d̷̡̪͇̺̆̀n̶̞̲̖̜̊̈́̊͜i̷͇̗̘̜͔̐̍͊̇Ẁ̷̒ͅe̶̫̍̍̓̌h̶̝̏̈́̋̚̚T̶̟͕͈͋́̑͊͠ţ̴̖̖͚͒̽͆̏s̵̗͖̀͒̃u̵̢̧̯̰̞̿̓J̷̗̽͛̓̇̓͜s̷̹̤̲͇̔͒͗͝ͅť̵̢̧̜̘ͅả̴̠͎͐ĥ̸͙̠͎̌̀̌͜͝T̸͉͂͠d̵̦̏̊̌n̷̨͕͇͙͛A̴͎̜̖͋̾̆͑̀d̴̢̛̪̱̂̾ë̵̠̩̙͈́͆͐̇ī̶͖͙̓̍̚ḫ̶̡̀̈́́p̴̨͓̥͕̂ō̴̥̺̿͝r̸̛̪̓̊t̴̮̜̓͋A̶̧͍͔͍̚è̴̬̆͐͌t̸̟͚͍̬̙͋͋̀̅͘ḯ̸̩͓́͝͝u̸̧̞̝͙̐͑̏Q̶̹̟̳̖̈́̾̉̾͜ş̴̱̜̭͓̊̈́͐̈̏s̴̺̲͓͓̳͑̎̃̆̑ẹ̸̖̦̀n̶̩̰̫͓͊̆̌ĺ̴̯ū̶̼̥̊͐̅ḟ̸̪̞͆̎̚͠ë̸̢̮͈́̇̈́͒̋p̸̪̿̊͗͑o̷̻͝Ḣ̶̫͎͐͛s̸̡̛̺̔͘̕̕í̴̮H̶̜͕͝s̸̳̭͔̗̣̃̉̉͠Ị̴̼͒s̸̩̫̙͍̏̃i̸̖̩̎͒̃h̸̬͎̠͓͐̇̔̀͐ͅT“
eht‘ :citpyrc tsom erew
.aedi on dah ynahteB
.dray eht ni eert mulp eht ot
fo ytirohtuA eht rednu“
,noitazilaer ni deknilb ehs nehT
.saw siht yrots fo dnik eht regnol on saw taht tuB
.daer ot elba eb dluow meht fo eno a ton
,ainrofilaC ni ytinummoc suoigiler egnirf a ni syad sih dedne
.eciohc rieht evah ot nwot elohw eht rof ytnelpa skooh gnilab ro ,swas-bmil ro
.tsew drazil denroh eht
.sesoprup lagel-yltcefrep-naht-ssel rof nem eseht deyolpme dah eh taht
.lla retfa ,tdleftatS hguorht skcart eht etuor ot denilced
,etanutrof saw hcihW
,natilopomsoc ,yttiw
dessefnoc eh hguoht
,setaicossa remrof s’terref eht gnomA
illengA dna kenareB fo ydotsuc eht ni deniamer ti fo klub eht tuB
eno ylno eht ton saw
.deifsitas yltnerappa saw eh hcihw htiw
.did yeht nehw ,sdrow eht fo yna dnatsrednu ot elbanu etiuq erew
̸̢̮̚e̸̟̹̼̽͊M̶̡͔̾͆͛̅̑͗̓e̷͔̰͔̔̎̿ę̶̈́͆̾͘S̵̗͒̎r̷̖͉̬̙̋̏̈́͗͋̀̐ͅe̶͕̤̗̠̍v̶̮͉̞̙̳̒͋̍̒̚͝e̴̛̹̣̲̯̋̐̚Ņ̴̼̝͇̺͕̺̈̎́͝l̷̥͇̣̾̍̍̆̕ļ̶̻̫̩̅̉͗͌͑͘͘u̷̻̱͂̈̓ỏ̷̢̥͈̰͙͒̀̈́Ÿ̷̡̨̨̭̰̲͔́͂̅͋̄̈͝h̷̨͕͂̋̿̓̊͠g̸̛̲̩̿͒́̐ͅȕ̸̡̱̼̮̖̣̙̊̍̌̎ǫ̴̞̩͔̐̄́̌͛̾̃h̷̡̢͍̫̙͚̲͠Ţ̵̰͙̳͒̓̆́̈́̋̕n̴̢̛̩͙̥̐̉͑̉͐͘͜ȅ̶̲͇͓̫͉̆́̐͗́v̶̖̥͉̖̟̻̄͜E“ .enog eb noos dluow nwot eht yhw saw siht ebyaM ”
,airetsyh ssam fo edosipe fo dnik emos fo sromur gnitic ,sroyevrus daorliar ehT — .dedne saw tI
.emit a nopu ecno ,gnos ylhtraenu na fo ekaw eht ni
ot hguone ykcul nahpro eht fo yrots eht
,thguac sevlesmeht dnuof
.tsaoC cificaP eht ro
,daed enots ,hctid a ni gninrom eno dnuof neeb dah
.redluohs eno revo ohcnop sih dessot retfird eht
.gnis dluoc nwot elohw eht mohw htiw ynomrah ni
siuL dna ynahteB
,gnignis nwod og oT
.esuoh htimS eht fo dray edis eht ni tuo
illengA dna kenareB fo seciffo wal eht
,dnal eht ,esuoh ehT
.dnatsrednu ot emit dah tey ton evah yeht taht swen gnitatsaved fo eceip emos draeh tsuj evah ohw nem ekil tub ,ezad a ni ro
.repsihw a ni neve moor eht ssorca elbidua saw taht eciov fo dnik eht dah eH
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
,elpoep s’siuL ,elpoep reh ,elpoep wen eht tnaem taht dna ”̴̢̲͕̭̈́ͅs̶̳͆̋̓̂ḋ̵̹̠̯̫n̶͍̝̎̃̌̊ä̷̬͎́Ș̶̛̼̫̼̏̋ę̵̳̭͑̏͐ͅḧ̷̡̘͎̤̣́̿͂͘T̶͕̟̐̌͒̈́͝n̶̹̳̣͐͝o̵̡̍̇͑͝p̷̧̳̳͓̜͗Ȗ̷͖̒̑̓̚ẹ̵̡͎͈̀́̔͝͝f̴̻̈͌ą̷̗̓̆Ŝ̵̰̟̩͙̮͗s̵̼͔̜̭̞̈è̸̞̌̿ȉ̸̢̮̰̎̽̂L̶̛̛͍̞̒̊͝e̵̼̤̞̐Ḩ̶̢̖̣̔̚͜ḙ̵̺̅̈́r̶̳̩͈̣͉̈́̅e̵̻͍̬͠h̷̛̲͌́͠W“ .seirots rieht derebmemer dna
,ecrof yb meht gnicalpsid
,sllih eht ssorca dehsurb ,mrif tub eltneg
.rehtona eno dedrager
:secnerefnoc dehsuh dna ytsah ynam fo etis eht saw siht ,erus eb oT
,lizarB ni edarap a ni decnad
,ynomrah ni os did ti tub ,gniraor saw dworc eht dnuora dniw ehT
.retfird eht dias ”,llew