namow siht taht siuL ot gninialpxe s’trebelgnE coD gnirongi ,dewollof ynahteB
ecnats rieht gnitfihs sevlesmeht dnuof ynahteB dna siuL sa tub
.gnignis s’retfird a yb desuac neeb dah siht taht
dias dna dias ehs htgnel ta tuB
noisserpxe s’siuL
”,gniht ylno eht s’taht sa esirprus oN“
.worbeye na desiar ynahteB
,denrecnoc saw htimS ynahteB sa raf sA  2 fo
tuo neddir d’ehS
,sregoR dna siuL revo dna
.eiuoL ta dekaorc eh ”?tfel
,dluoc eh revewoh drawtsew yaw sih gniparcs yob sselerutuf ,sselenutrof a neeb d’eh nehw toN
”?hagus ,noolas eht dhawot kcab ydal ’lo na ’nipleh dnim uoy dluoW
,lohocla fo draeh erofeb reven d’ehs fi sa
taht naht rehtruf etats a sniatnuom eht ni dnuof ssap wen a spahrep
,yenom evah ton did eh nehW
,gnignis sih ekil gnihton saw ,ekops eh nehw ,eciov sih ”,em lleT“
.detcejretni eiuoL
kcen s’beJ ot gnulc ynahteB
:yas ot gniyrt neeb dah
,riaffa rieht s’taht llew ,swen eht raeh ot yppah eb nog t’nia yeht fI“
,reporp eiriarp eht no ,nwot eht edistuo ydaerla saW
”?yawyna ,ninrom eht ni ylrae os dnal ham no tuo
.deddon retfird ehT
,eciov rehtona deffocs ”,neht naw’G“
.pu tup ot secnef adnik tahw ediced ot tog sa eno eht t’nsaw eh tub
derepmah rehtar erew skramer gnittuc sih
.erew seitiroirp reh tahw yltcaxe wenk ,syawla sa ,aM
,kaeps ot hguone derevocer yllanif siuL
ton s’tI“ .moor eht
.og ot desoppus saw siht woh neeb evah llew yrev yam tahT
.timov ot ton gniyrt yltnerappa dna beJ tsniaga gninael
,noissap a htiw eriw debrab detah eH
.ti nihtiw rednuht tnatsid eht
erew sleehw dna sevooh fo dnuos eht dna
”,ynahteB ssiM ,gninroM“
.luficnaf tahwemos gnieb fo tnuocca taht detcepsus ynahteB
.ti ot teg tbuod on d’ehs hguoht
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,floWcaM boR yb ”eM hguorhT dna
ykSehTfOegdEehTtAhcraMsniatnuoMyerG .gnas ehs ”̴̠̘̂̄͗ý̴̝̈́̃k̴̡̓͛̆͂̽S̸͉̪̰̞̈́é̶͓̙͖̺͊̕ĥ̸̟̲ͅŤ̵̢͚̻͇̠͒͑̈́͊f̶͎̣͖͜͠O̷͔͊̐̒̈́́ȇ̵̢͓͚̬͂̌g̷̭̺̑̊ḑ̴̪̘̟͌E̷̥̳̭͒͐̔͐̊ĕ̴͖̆͗͛h̴̡̲̯̠͖͂͝T̷̼̻̼̣̟̏̈́t̴̡̤̊̇A̴̟̾̋h̴̡̛͇̼͑̈́̈́c̸̫̞̩̊̾ŕ̷̨̖̹̄͑͊̉a̷͔̞͋M̷̳̈́̈̈́͐ŝ̵̟̖̈́n̶͙̮͍̻͋͑ǐ̵͔͍̉͝ą̵̛̙͌̅̈́t̵̜͇̯͌͌͒̔n̷͍̰̤̈̿̌̃̄û̷͍͍̐́͌o̸̜͖̗͂̓M̵͕̠͔͔̤̒̌̊̄y̸͉̦͎̖̾̾̔ẻ̶͇̆͘̕r̴̞̳̲̫͊̌́̕G“
.tsud eht ni despalloc efaR revo demool eH
t’ndid eH“ .ollidamra ehT ”.did erus eh ,risseY“
,retfird eht edisgnola ,efaR ecaf ot
”eM hguorhT dna ,enO yloH
,si eh tahw neve spahrep dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,pu dehctih beJ teg s’tel lleW“
.woleb ssarg trohs eht ni noitatiga ni gnicap mussop eht dna
,ylhtooms os dna ,yltpmorp os detraped ehS
.htimS royaM yllaicepse
”.si siht revetahw
.ettemalliW eht rof setaredefnoc decargsid
”,wonk I fi denmaD“ ”?nam eht htiw gnorw s’tahw“
”̷̨̩͙̖̟̃̐͋͂͗y̶̭̭͎͖̗̔̀́̕k̶̛̬̼̈́̋͝S̴̻͈̺̗͕͂̍̚͝ḛ̸̩̯͕̒h̶̠̱̳̀̇̀T̴͉̓͂͑̕f̸̤̝͂̄Ȍ̸̙̒̿s̷̛͇̮̟̲̹̃̍̐͘t̶͉͙̘̫͈̓́͘r̵̼̭͎̩͇̽̃a̴͔̍̅p̸̨̢̬̣̟̄̆̕m̷͕̠̬̲͚̒a̸̼͔̟̹̓Ȑ̸̜͕̹̥̍̌̕͘ę̴̛͖̮̩͗̀͊h̷͕̮͈̑̈́̄T̷͎͉͙̘̪͑̃́̈́s̴͍̮̿͌̓͒̈s̷̳͌̑̾͗̿ó̸̼̞͓̺͠ͅr̴̩͌̓͛̊́c̵̨̝̪̈̓͋͊̍Ȁ̴̳̥̦̳̞d̶̳̳̍̈́̉̕ḗ̶̤͉̓̈́̍g̸̹͇̪̿ŕ̶̗͉̟a̶̙̓h̸̺̖̼̲͓͑̉̏C̴͓̫̘͖̉̀s̴͇̥̪̖͑͘n̸͉̮̲͝ḯ̵̞̝́́a̵̮͎͒t̶͇̻̙̚ṇ̴̠̙͂̇̍ú̷͓͉̮͖̗̾͗̊͌õ̸͚͉̾̊̃͜Ṃ̷̝̦̽ȳ̸̺͍̹̟̓̄͒ė̴͉̖r̵͙̙̤̞̅G̷̛̩͇͉̋̂ṉ̷͈͈̩̞̔ě̷̛͕̏h̴̨̫̩̞̓̆̾̏W“ .pollag dluoc esroh a naht retsaf
,ti tsniaga teef reh peek ot gnilggurts saw
.ees reven dluow ynahteB secalp eht fo yna ot yaw rieht no
yrt ot hguone esolc erew yeht fi neve taht ecaf reh no kool a dna
”?naem uoy ,deneppah ti woH“
”.̴͙̆́̕e̷̘̬͐̊͑̈́̋i̸͓͍̰͐̊͐̾Ḋ̵̮̤̬̞͘o̶̻̗̭̾T̴̡̛̝̰̖̎̆͊t̴͔̬̒́̈̄͝n̶̩͔̦̲͇̅̔̌̈́e̶̱͓͇͗͒́W̵̢̰͖̤̋̇͑̚t̴͈̟̀Į̴̳͔͆̽̇ẙ̶̲̫͓̺͑a̶̩͓̯̫͍͒D̶̩͛̕e̵̥͔̻͍͑͝ȟ̷̝̭̝T̴̳͍̽a̸̧̛͚̣̥i̷͔͉̙̼̊̍u̷̬̽͂͜l̸̲͝ę̶̯͇̪͋̋ͅḽ̶̜͙̅l̸̠̯̽̆͝A̴̩̱̤͉̒d̶͖̗̦̔͂͗̉è̵͔i̷̺͉̓̽̒̓̚r̷̥̂̏͋͘C̴̢̨̧̺̗̕d̵̩̲̥͚̈́n̶͔̯̍̎̅͐͜i̶̫̦̫͙̅̓̓W̷͕̘͔̟͈̽è̶̢͍̯͖̕̚͝h̸͍̦͇͔̬́̀́̄͠T̶̢̄̇̚d̶̟̳̖͍̈̓͊̌͝ń̸͖̞̪͔̺̉̉A“ .gnirettulf seye
,nahpro luftcepser dna gnikrowdrah eht
,elleb nwot gnortsdaeh ehT .tniop siht ta
ereh siuoL ylerus taht tceffe eht ot noitpurretni eltbus-yldrah s’rehtom reh dna
”-yas d’aP ruoy tahw wonk uoy ,woN“
”.rotcod a ot mih teg nac ew fi ees“
dednimer ynahteB ”!erom on eman sih wonk t’nod eh tuB“
noolas a ni luawretac neknurd a osla saw nmyh lepsog a fi sa dednuos cisum ehT ”̸̧̭̟̪̓y̵̗͖̳̅͋̓l̸̝̰̤̟̿̑F̵̡̩̣̩̯̈͆ǫ̸̗͇̬̽́̑̄̽T̷͓̦̠̋̊͠w̷̧̱͇̒́͘ǫ̷̝̱̈́̀H̷̟̬̮̹̅̀͌̌̍s̶͚̪̈́́̈̊͜w̷̨̛̝̯̝̳̌̉͂ȏ̵͕̼̲̙͗̓͠͝n̶̬̳͈͗̎̑̅̏K̶̩̒l̵̼̩̟̒̉̏̿l̵̯̘̟͛͒̎ͅͅi̴̧̛͐͗̇̏t̵̡͗S̶̨̰̤̲̹̊̀̓͛t̸̛͓̞̄̓e̵̪̊̏Y̶̧̼̫͊̀̽̄̆o̴̮̩͍̬̖͑̓̇̊̀g̵͎̮͔̟̳̾A̵̞̝̥̙͒̋̕͜g̵̡͖͉͛̈́̆n̷̻̤͉̘̜̂ơ̸̭̟̩̬̿̏̚L̷̦͕̠̔̄͜͜ḑ̷̜̅͌̆͑͝ę̸̺̣͘ì̸̖̖̭̋̑D̵̤̲̦̭͍̀ḑ̸̻̬́̾̀͐n̵̦͔̥͂̓̌í̷̻̗̻̽̅͌W̵̬̊̌͌̀͐e̷̫̕h̵̻̬̦̮̮̾̓̆̾̕T̶̼̙͊̍͑͝f̸̬̆͊̋̽̌O̶̮̱̯̞͕͛͘l̵͕̦̒̆̒l̶̖̓͋̆͂̚A̵͉̯͔̯͋̓̒̀ŵ̴̞͠o̷̲̻͊̎͂̕͝H“ ?gnineppah saw tahW
,ecaf reh tes ehs
,ekaL tlaS rof dnuob snomroM eb thgim esehT
.rohtua eht yb daeR
”.deneppah ti woh ’niredisnoc“ ,devresbo siuL
emehcs fo dnik tahw
.sdrow elbisneherpmocni eht fo sisahpme citeop tnerappa ni
,dray thgierf dna noitats dna skcart rof esahcrup ot deen dluow enil liar gnimoc eht dnal tahw yltcaxe tuo dnif
:stsop gnidart morf worg taht stiurf fo stros eht otni demossolb dna
”onafreuH siuL“ won oS
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf seigolohtna yna otni
saw daorliar eht wenk htimS royaM tnatropmi woh meht dnimer ot
”.od I esruoC“ .deknilb ssibroC
.keew tsal ecnis selim owt n’erom dessergorP
erac ro eveileb ot demees ydobon woh ralugnis tsom saw ti taht
.dedulcnoc ynahteB
.ylimaF htimS eht fo rebmem a fo tohsrae nihtiw detsixe
,dehgis eiggaM ”,yenoh lleW“
”!ssibroC won ssenisub nisserp erom tog ew hcihw
”̸̧̨̛͉̙̇̊s̸̩̖̮̭͖̊͛̀̑̕ḍ̴̙̭͇͉͘d̵̙̞͍̉Ȯ̴̱͐e̷̡̻̞͓͙͝ĥ̵͖͙̟̮̓T̴̼͛̈́̋͊͜͠s̵̖̔͂͜t̵̥̞͛̇n̸̨̜̪̣̈́́̇̏̒ṵ̵̈́́͌̈̉o̴̘̤̤̻͒̔̊͗C̷̨̰̀̇́͠r̴̻̺̽̓͘e̵̬̊v̵̫̟̠͈̄̌e̸̱͙͊Ń̷̻̰̿͝d̶̢͖̠̜̣͌̈͘͠n̷̢̙̼̤̳̓Ȃ̴̮̰̌͠ṃ̴̨͛̇̍ͅì̸̱̟͓̰͌̒́̕h̶̢͍̫̰̓̈́͒̊́ͅp̵̤̘̎͗͌͆á̸̜̹̖͙̈́̿r̸̳̭̻̳̹̔̒͛e̸̮͎͐͒̓S̴̼̰͑̓̀͗̕e̴̢̅͘h̵̛̼̲̆̕T̸̨̬͕̺̺͛͝s̴͈̪̮̽͆̉̂̃À̵̩̤̏̎̄s̷̥͉̟̲̀͒͌̌I̴͉͙̬̾d̸̩̞̭̽͋ͅņ̶̺͍͌̈́̓̄ĭ̶̡̘͍̽̉͆̕Ẅ̶̡̳̹̫́̋̋e̸̡͝h̴̲̩̕T̴͓̭̒͑͛̈́͝r̶̹̰̩̔̐͑̕ö̴̗̻͓̖̮́́̋̅̕F̷̳̋̉͊̈́s̶̛͍̤̀̓̆͠d̸̡̪̗̋̿̔̈́̈ò̵̧̘̰̫G̸̨̝̭̭̈̐̕f̵̨̲̬̳̐ͅO̶̡͕̗̝̒̈́̇͒̈́t̷̟̕n̶͎̍̀́̚͝ȩ̶̢̪̍̾m̸̗̝͂̊͘h̵͕̱͚̅͒́͜s̸̻͓̘̙̒̃̕͝͝ͅi̷̡̺̊n̸̨̨͎̥̳̉̏̽͘o̶͚̮̳͊͒̃̊͊ͅt̸̺̿̓ͅs̴͚͔̲͎̯̐̏A̶͔̪͎̣̹̽̈̈ę̵͔̞̤̦̈́h̵̢͕̥̲͗̊̎͠T̷̡̹̥͋d̶̙͍͑͝͠ȅ̴̛̗̳̝̥͠o̴̡̤̪̗̖̅͛͛̑ḩ̵͈͙̦̈́̃͆̅ċ̵̗̱̩͓̝͒E̴̬̭͑͗͘ś̵̺͖̽̒͊́n̷̼̬͇͊̉i̷̜̟̓̀á̵̖̐t̶̡̠̗̳̿̓ͅn̸͔͕̚ù̶̺̞̺̯̺̚o̶̺͖̮̣͑̈̑̆̋M̸̨̀k̸̡͙̻͙͑̏c̵̨̨̰͎͖̐͛̈́̓ą̶̣̜͔͐l̸̛̼̻͕̪̍̍B̴̨̺̾̆̄͌e̴̝̺̤̾h̶͇̦̬̦́͋̔͜T“ .noilednad a dewehc beJ ,denrecnocnu ,reh htaeneB
neewteb ecnereffid on raeh ot demialc
ytilatot sti ni dnal taht denwo enola yeht dna yeht erus ekam ot
.yats ot nosaer on dah yeht esuaceb tub ,og ot erehwyna dah yeht esuaceb ton wolf eht htiw gniog-
”,oot ’ningis eerht lla saw ew ylneddus dnA“
raf yb gnitatirri erom saw ti tuB
.debrevir a fo tuo gnidilg tsim nmutua etal a ekil dehcaorppa dna ,dnoces a deruop
setaf etamitlu eht sa llew sa
.ereh morf ,ees ot hcum t’nsaw erehT
.eman sih yllaer t’nsaw ,esruoc fo ,eiuoL
,troppus rof gnulc
,deplug eiggaM ”,yaserad hA“
,yawyella eht ni gnidnats ohcnop deroloc tsud a ni
.dnal pu pans ot ti desu eh ,yenom dah eh nehW .detca eh
.esnopser a saw yoj tnerehocni fo sraet hguorht yks eht otni pu gnizag sselnu
”?esoppus t’nod uoy ,lla ta gnihctac
”.esruoc ,uoy ot niklaT“
,htron gniog sevird elttac eht ylppus ot
.cificaP eht drawot sliart nogaw eht ot ekat ot deripsni sevlesmeht dnuof syawla srobhgien esoht wohemos dna
.noitingocer ni fi sa ,deddon eh dna
revo levart fo maerts niam eht degdun yllaudarg dah—
retaw looc fo reppid nit eht deyojne efaR
,ecremmoc s’noitan taerg siht fo erutuf eht ot
,nwodwohs gnignilsnug lanif a ot snoisnet eht evird ,sedis on ekat ot ydaer
”?kcab ereh efaR teg ot woh ro ,detnaw eh tahw
”?yaw siht lla tuo uoy sgnirb
etoyoc a saw ereht
,eman a yllautca t’nsaw
,dessorc dah sliart eht yad eht ni kcab tuB
.did etarepsed eht dna wef eht ylnO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
amaM ot gnidrocca
”-fi wonk t’nod I ,ma’aM ,hU“
kcalb eht ni terref ynwarcs eht ecaf ot dnuora denrut neve d’ehs erofeb
.ria eht otni gnisir tsud fo spsiW
,daeh sih koohs eh nehT
:eerf rof siht uoy evig ll’I dnA“
,noitcejretni suovren s’siuL ffo tuc ehs ”,yadakceH eiggaM“
.gnidliub saw eh ecnef eht fo edis rehto eht no tlah a ot esroh reh werd mussop eht
,derettum ynahteB
,eM ni gniS“   yojne esaelP
.eromyna emanrus sih pu gnignirb derehtob reven ollidamra eht taht evah ot klat hguone gnitartsurf a saw taht dnA ”.siuoL“ dna ”siuL“
,eciov rehto siht raeh ylraelc ot drah saw tI
”.liart eht ffo deparcs tnargav emos tihs a eceip ytrid
.detalupopnu yleritne saw
snoitartsurf rehto eht fo ynam naht
,delims terref ehT
”,ti evah ydaerla d’ew ,erew’t fi esoppus I“
tub yas ot gnihton fo kniht dluoc ynahteB ”?taht saw“
.railimaf gnol si ,rehtegot nehw ,mrof yeht yrots eht dna
”nahpro eht ,siuL“ saw siht
,sredluohs sih dehcnuh siuL
lleW“ ?tnuocca eht draeh neve d’ehs erofeb dnA
”.ssenisub emos ot ees ot tog hA ,em esucxe ll’klof uoy fi woN .havocer ’nog t’nia osla eh tuB
.snogaw eht revo htoclias hguor dedaf ehT
rartsigeR deeD ytnuoC eht dna llaH ytiC revo lortnoc s’aP dna yenom s’aM esu
.elbadaernu saw noisserpxe s’yadakceH .srM
.yssim ,yrots rey“
.rohtua eht yb daer ,floWcaM boR yb
.nwot ot resolc nitteg er’s’royevrus eht
,trebelgnE coD ,ssibroC ,stnerap reh taht efil s’ynahteB fo noitartsurf tsetaerg eht yldrah saw tI
.tsew gniog srelttes eht
”.saw eh erehw r’eman sih derebmemer efaR fi deksa eh“
.ssarg eht hguorht dniwnwod gnitfird nexo dicalp fo llems ehT
,taoc dna triks gnidir lacitcarp a ni
.ecnarongi etelpmoc dedneterp enoyreve tey
flesreh tcaf ni saw flesreh edisni revetahw dna ,htuom reh tuo dna reh nihtiw snoiger elbaknihtnu morf gniwolb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,duolc livna na ekil deraer
,nwot elohw eht htiw sthgif suoinomirca ,nellus ,ylrus dekcip eh
.esucxe na saw tahT
sregoR nopu detisiv neeb dah
.ynahteB ssiM tub ydoboN
”?hus ,taht si yltcax‘“
,dias d’ehs ,sseug d’ehS
,dnopser ton did terref ehT .deppans ssibroC ”!efaR !ereht yA“
,deneppah gnihtemos nehW
.ereh tuo saw ehs snosaer laer eht fo eno neeb dah niart nogaw eht ta gnikooL
ti otni gnillaf ot
,siuL ,ynahteB fo
.tlef ehs sa tnemhsinotsa delffab hcum sa ni
.nobruob a ot flesreh gnipleh yltnerappa
rolraP tnorF ylimaF htimS eht dellac eb yletarucca erom htob dluoc hcihw
.levarg ro lworg tuohtiw tub yhtaerb ,rewol
…tuoba nihton yas
htiw krow ot gnitartsurf hsilived saw ffuts eht
,reh dniheb ssarg llat eht hguorht yaw sti gnikam saw eciov rehtona ”̸͕̅̑̏̈͑ę̷͉̪̯̅̆͊̉͘y̸̯͎̮̮͌̄͗È̵̩͒̈d̴̅̉̒̒͠ͅē̸͇̼̥͕͘w̵̰̙̎ͅo̶̜͐r̸̳͔̯̥̓r̵̬̼̜͕͛͊a̶̟̲̲͆́N̷̛̻̪̲̔͊̋ͅͅA̷͉͎͎̫͐̀̃̾́h̴̲͂͆͘g̶̥̭̈́͠͝u̷̙͒́̑ò̶̲͜r̶͈̘̓̇h̴̯̤͊̂͂̒͠T̸̡̛̟̑̑͛͘ȑ̶̤̩̪̓̕ͅê̶̯̔w̶̭̻̠̙̒͌ọ̴̱̆̄͛l̴̨̘̾͛̕͠Ǵ̷̣͙̭s̷͈͎̍́n̷̨̥͛̓̈́̑̿ï̷͓̀̚̕͘ḁ̸̟̮̣̉ͅt̵͔̻̣̼̩̑ń̷̝̪̮̊̓̏͝ũ̸̦̈́o̴̧̩̺̲̘̎̄Ḿ̶̪̂̀̈́͠ḱ̴̢̛̭̟͕̎͒̚r̷̩̬̘̜̗͆ǎ̴̧̹̳̭̓͒͠D“ .eciov ylno eht t’nsaw s’reh tuB
na llac d’namrepapswen eht tahw si haeh siht“
,esroh a no ,mussop a tsuJ
”,rissoN“ ”?taht ekil...“
,stnaw retfird suoiretsym siht tahw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
redic s’rednatsyb sselerac yna nrut ot gninetaerht rehtaF citsoerepA na ekil detfil sdnah ,sehcnarb kao ekil daerps smra
,riahc rab a sa nwonk osla
.yrellag yrruFoS sih no
,serots sdoog yrd ,snoolas
,htiw no gnitteg eb ot serohc dah
.llih eht fo pot eht dehcaer ehs nehw
.flesti kcuf dna og dluoc liarT nogerO eht
.tdleftatS ni toof tes ot yaw rieht fo tuo yad a flah og ot evah dluow relttes a woN
!em evag droL dooG eht esnes eht htiw ereh eno ylno yltnerappa dna“
.gniggagyllol hguonE
,erofeb draeh t’ndah ynahteB eciov a deksa ”,woh ’nA“
,saw yeht n’fi uoy ta taolg emoc neht dna ,era yeht hcihw
,siuL ta syawedis decnalg dna ,niks ybbonk kciht tlef ehs
”̸̢̡͍̥̆̈͠s̸͍͒̀ș̵͙͇̂͗̊ä̵̲̗́̉̇̄Ṗ̷̡̳̀ṣ̶̜̮̫͒t̷̥̼͕̱̾Ï̴̟̓n̷̞̰͍̍̀I̵̡͚̩͕̼͂͛̕͝t̶̛͙̥̍I̶̙͌y̶͈̽á̵͉͉̬͕̦̿̕̕̕t̷̼̥̞͈̃̊̐S̷̨̗̻̫͠r̷̥̆̈͘͠O̶̢͙͓̯͍̎̽̈̂d̷͙̺̦̂̒ṇ̶͙̅̈́î̸̡͓͖͊̈̕̕W̸̝̞̃̅̇̕͝ḛ̵̎̀͘h̸̙͇̽T̸̨̘̯̥͉͊͗̾̈͋t̸̢͛l̵͉͚̱̦̼̏͊̾a̸̜͌͒͝͠H̷̬̗̉̾͠d̷̼̖̘̞̀̓̂̆ḻ̶͙̝̥͂͛ų̷͇̫̬͔̾o̴̢̧̫̅͆̈́̃̚C̶̗͆s̸͖̜̱̎̎̃́a̶̛͓̟͒W̸̱͗è̵̮͙̫̩͇͒̐͒̉h̵͈͔̾T̸̢̙̠̎g̵̝͙̦̖̋̅̉̀͠n̷̳͐̅̀͘͝į̴̺͉͉̽̇͊̒͠h̶͙̒̎̏͛͠t̵̝̫̄́̿o̵̯̲̠̯̣͋̉̉̚Ń̸͚̔̂͊r̷̨̭̗̊̃o̵͓̎̄̓F“ .yleritne yawa nwolb eb ehs tsel
.kcab htaerb reh teg ot thguof ehs sa
.ot depmuj neeb dah hsinapS kaeps t’nseod eno nehw ot spmuj eno snoisulcnoc fo dnik eht tub
.deirub erew yeht erus dna doog edam dah ssibroC ekil nem ,htiw enod dna revo erew sevird elttac eht
.sllih eht fo edis rehto eht ot
,tah reh debbarg ehs
,kcab deppans ssibroC
.resolc yna teg t’ndid ehS .elbaivnE
.elbats yrevil eht dniheb
,riahc siht ni gninnirg reh neeb ev’dluoc ti wenk ehs lla rof taht tuo tniop ot regae
.noitanitsed ro seiceps rieht ta sseug ot ,srelttes eht tuo ekam ot yawa raf ooT
.ydemer a sa sseltiurf devorp ti tub
.weiv otni deppets regnis eht yllaniF
,dniw dloc fo tnerrot a ekil tlef cisum ehT
,gnitfihs revo etats a revir a spahrep—
.dexaler sredluohs sih dna ,dekrep srae sih
”.nahpro“ rof hsinapS saw ti
?pu dekool yeht fi ees yeht dluow tahw dnA
,erom yna rood txen t’nsaw ti tnaem ti fi
,esolc werd ehs sa fooh a pu dleh trebelgnE coD ”,ssim ,ecnatsid ym peek dluohs I“
.suoigatnoc t’nia tneitap ruoY
”…s’eh ylneddus dna dnah hcnar ym ta sgnis oboh tnuocca-on emoS
,psarg t’ndluoc ynahteB taht seinomrah gnittih meht neewteb erew meht fo ruof eht ”̴̦͈͔̬͙͛́͛̀s̸̰͍̀̇s̴̺̦̄a̶͙̠̋̃̋l̴̪͔̆͊G̵̛̩͙̒̒̕r̵͍̾̉ĕ̵̲̎̇͜v̷͍̠̯̲̽l̸̙̠̫̙͖̈́̑ȋ̸̟̺͖͎̓̈͋̔Ś̶̗̰͓̆̈́̄t̵̜̭̮͙̦̎̈́̀̾̕f̶̛̘̥͂̏̉o̶̡̦̓̀͒͂S̸̯̪̙̣͗̿̈̂̋o̸̘͋t̴̩̞̦͆͒̚n̶͖̠̤̈́̍̏̀̉İ̶̳͌͜͜d̸̯͔̭̝͇̿e̵̥̺̓͂́̎r̷͎͉͔̓̈́̽͗͑ė̸̖͈̏t̴̳͋̄̎̀t̵͙̠͈̺͙̉͛͂͆͌a̴̢͈̯̓͂̂͜͝h̸̛̲̽̋͊S̸̮̜͔̻̔̽s̵̢̨͓̺͌̐̊d̵͍͑̃̍͘͝n̶̡̧̮͈̏̔͂̅ͅâ̷̠̬͎̞̮̽̕b̸̫̄̂̒ṋ̵͗̉̉̚i̶̝͎͒̋̕ä̶́͜R̵̛̛͔̙̠͑͌̋ē̴̘̱̦̍͆͒ḩ̴̞̳̤͚̒T“ .eugnot sih ffo gnillor cisum eht htiw elbatrofmoc yleritne dekool eh ,saw eh reveohW ”̷̤̭̽̂ȇ̷̞́̐i̸̧̛͎̹̞͐̕̕͜Ḍ̶͍̱̞̝͗̃͌̑͘o̷̦̼̻̫͋̒̇͘͝T̴̹͖̹̳͆̽́t̸̨̨͓̼̤̿̀̈́̌n̵̛̹̣̮̈͒̒̕ẻ̵̡͎̣̑̐͘W̷̘̦̙͑̇t̵̻̪͓̼̋̈́̆̚Î̷̡̛̖̒̆y̷̡͈̙̪̘̓a̸̬̱̪͐̀̄́̕D̵̤̰͚̲͌̂͐͝e̶̟̙͙̮̖͑͑͝ĥ̶̲͍̻̘̆ͅT̸̛̟͚͕̓m̶̞̫̪̀͆͋͑e̷̮͍͐͠i̸̙̮̗̾͆͊͊u̷̞̰̯̿̄̋q̸͚͐̐͘ḛ̷̦̇R̴̹̺̜̺̈̽̑͗͘ͅÅ̷̢̾̐̈g̶͕̺̗̒̏̊͘n̴̝̦̪͂a̸̡̪̪̟̋̂́͛̓S̶̜͐̓̀d̷̞̼͉͓̏̄̅̚n̷̖̑ï̴͉̘̤̅̒ͅẄ̷̡̛͔̭͖͓́̒e̴͉̜̩̒̀h̴̥̗̿͗͝T“ .haisseM eht fo doolB otni
,riahc noitanimaxe na ssorca delwarps terref lufssilb eht morf pu kool t’ndid trebelgnE coD
eiriarp eht ssorca gnipeews mrotsrednuht a sa llew sa
:lrig gnuoy a saw ehs nehw neeb d’yeht sa nommoc sa t’nerew yehT
saw ehs raen ylsuolirep
…sej eh neht dnA“
a ot niklat nees nieb reh tuoba yas d’aP reh tahw reh llet“
”?no drow deen sklof daorliar eht nihton eb t’noW“
.gnola gnas eh taht gnidnatshtiwton
,ereh tuo saw ehs nosaer a t’nsaw taht tuB
,daeh s’efaR yb gnittauqs saw eiuoL ”?ew oD“
?eman ruoy rebmemer uoy od“
!enod I sa esitrepxe lanoisseforp ’sregoR ni tseretni na hcum sa tsuj tog ev’sklof nwo reY“
.gnihtemos ot tcaer ot woh gniwonk ton dna
1 traP ,floWcaM boR yb
,lles ot desufer srobhgien nehW
.sdrow ton saw tuo emac tahw
:rehtohcae gnivol rof htob meht setah taht elcsum derih elbitpmetnoc eht
.ti timda ot desufer ehs tub
.serutsap s’ssibroC a-eno gnola tuo
”.ecaf ylgu ruoy ssorca porc ’nidir ym dah ev’uoy retfa kaeuqs llits nac uoy n’fi dnif ’nog er’ew dna niaga ecneserp ym ni kaeuqs uoY“ .tah
dniw eht no ti draeh ohw
.ti od ot dah ohw eno eht tsuJ
,erutcip eht etelpmoc ot
”,onafreuH .rM ,em no tcejbus eht egnahc ot yrt uoy t’nod os ,syawla sa emaS“
ycarucca tcefrep htiw
.gnignis saw ehs tahw aedi on dah ehS
’,neht won‘ htiw evig ot tnaem eh hceeps yna detrats syawla aP ”,coD neht woN“
.emoc d’eh sa ylsuoiretsym sa tesnus eht otni ffo edir neht dna
,enoyna eb thgim yeht ereh morF
.emit htderdnuh evif ro htfif eht neewteb erehwemos rof tuo yalp tnemugra siht raeh ot deen on dah ehs ecnis
azilE ssiM ot gnidroccA
?erac ot mees worc siht did yhw tuB
”.oot gnis su fo eerht eht lla edam eH
,sdnah sih ni revo tah sih denrut siuL ”,llew hA“
.fo dir eb ot dalg saw eh snedrub erew
reens a otni gnilruc dehsinif spil s’ynahteB ”,sregoR“
,rehtona eb d’erehT
,won ,sregoR ta gnignis erew meht fo eerht eht
...“ .efaR ot deneppah ,tcaf ni ,dah tahw aedi tsethgils eht ton dah eh taht ni
gnissap niart nogaw a saw erehT
,deraeppa evah dluohs retfird suoiretsym a tbuod oN
,reh htiw deerga ohw sklof eht nevE
.ti fo drow a ton ekops yeht tey dnA
,seenk sih ot knas sregoR dna
.detseggus ehs sa od ot ssibroC rof tiaw ot rehtob ton did ehS
,ssibroC eteP ruoS neeb d’eh nehw ron
’kcuf‘ ekil drow a taht timda ot naht retteb wenk
,evael ot tog esle reveohw taht reh gnitnuat
.niar tnatsid fo llems eht dna knird gnorts ekil dnim reh ni gnar yeht tub
”?srM ,thgirla uoy erA“
.yawyna esu ot derehtob neve ydobon taht eman eht saw
.esle gnihtyna fo kniht yeht dluoc
…tuoba od nac ew tahw aedi tsetniaf eht tog t’nod I ?yltcaxe ,tahW“
.remmus snialp taerg eht fo ssenetal eht etipsed ,dloc erew ti fi sa
”̵̲̿̈́m̸̧̤̒͆͂̑ͅi̴̠̩͇̤̊̈́͠D̷̞͗̀͌͊ś̵̜̺̎̈̎ẃ̶̢͇̗͔̏͝ơ̷̝͎̠͋̓̄r̸̡̮̘͈͆̾́͑͠G̴̛̥̿̈̕e̵̢̪̜̓̅̋̚p̸̜̈́̅͗̔ǫ̸̖́̆̾͂͝H̷͔̺̲̪͌͗͊̐n̵̢̙͚̖̉ͅe̷͍̮̿͛̇h̷̫͇͐͜͝W̴̥͙̅g̸̠̃̉͆̽ͅń̷̪̈͝ö̷̭̬̱̝̼́̔̋͘s̵̡̠͊̌̌͌̔n̷̙̪͔̠̬̅e̶̛̥̱̓̓͘v̸̥̈́̋̀͆̿E̸̅̂͗̇͂ͅt̸͙̤̩̬̃̉͠A̵̱͎̽͝g̵̨̧͔͔͖̿͘n̸̲̿̈́í̴͈̟̼͆͌̀S̸̹̣̀̌̋͐͜͜͝o̶̧͇̙̮̺͋́T̷̢̧̼͙̈́n̴̫̜̍̿̇͘m̶̜̄̍̒̍̚ỳ̶̹̲̮ͅḦ̶̩̘͈́A̴̫̲̫̍n̵͎̕m̷͐́͜y̶̠̭͊̌̒̕H̷̡̭̠̯̾͝d̶̹̖̫̟̫͛ē̴͍̜̺̹̬̽͝ṛ̸̍̊̚ẹ̶̯̘̥̩͗̊͘̕b̴͎̉͝m̷̺̰̥̝̙̿͊̇̒̐ȅ̸̥̐̊m̷̢̺̹̩͓͠e̶̛̛̋̽͜R̴̝͚͓̍̈̈̀̔f̷̧̭̱͙̊ĺ̵̲̑a̴̳͐̔H̸̖̙̺̓̎ͅḀ̵͔͙͚͒͊̀̚ē̵̛̛̜̅̚k̷͖̩͖͉͗͊i̷̡͎̋̿̎L̶̠̜͈̄̐́͘ͅs̴̻̠̗̜̫̒e̵͍͊͗͗ş̶̢̦̹̄̏͗̌̓i̵̖̱͔̺̓̈̂͠ͅR̵̻͕͔̠͊͊t̸̡̢̥͉̎Ì̴̲͔̀̾̑s̴̘̝̅͐A̷̯̞̩̮͆̒̈́̎ͅs̷̯͕̈́̉ę̸̟̮͋ͅh̵̨̢̜̹͋́s̴͉̟͔͋͐͊u̷̖̳͒̊̉̚͝R̵̢̜̬͎̀͂t̷̨̛̟͓͚̬̀̄̾I“ .gnignis esiwekil erew ohw
!gninnur nwot siht peek ot tog su fo emos“
”̶̨̪̭̘͐t̴̙̰̻̍s̷̪̩͎͈̃̚̚a̵̠͇̗̥̓̆̀̂L̴̠͓̐͂̅̏̕t̶͕̑̕Ā̵͍̘̱̤̭̒͗d̴̯̾̎́̕ȩ̵͈̠̓͌͐ḯ̵̹͚̲̂͊ͅD̸̩̤͗̂̌́d̶̡̯͆̊̅̂n̵̢͍͓͔̺̆̅́̐̔ĩ̵̗̘͔ͅW̴̜͍̖̓͌ḛ̴̤̎̾̌ḣ̵̢͎͖͎T̶̰͚̑̚͠ͅṅ̴̝͙̬͎ĕ̴̫͎͙̞̓̓̕͠h̴̞͐̂W“ .reh nihtiw ro dniheb ro htaeneb erehwemos ,cisum fo ssyba na saw erehT ”̵̧̣̘̳͑r̴̳̠͒̀̓ȕ̴̡̘͕͌̿ó̵͈̫͍̜̹̊H̵̲̹̗̔̃͠e̸͙͈̝͛̅̌h̷̡̞̘̻̅̅́͝Ţ̷͓̯̯͇̄͠e̸̬͒̐̂͝c̸͎̏͗̓à̸̯̺̲͒̒̏͠l̸͇̤̬̻̰̔͠P̷̫͉̭̽̉̈́͋ȓ̵̻̚ͅO̴̙͒̔̓y̸̹̪̅̾̇̋̀ạ̸͍̘͒̈́̉̉́D̸̗̱͕̓̿͛͝ḙ̷͕̜͕͛h̶̤͖̑͑̕T̶̨̤̈́̚k̸̞͎̣̓͗̇͗̾r̸̡͖̹͔͆̊͛̇̑ͅa̷̡͉̮̒͑͌̃M̷̫̱̥̓̑̋̚͝n̷̦͔̬̜̄ȁ̸͓̺̀̇̀̐C“ .tnetni dna noitcerid detfihs dah gnos eht leef dluoc ynahteB ”̸̬̽͆̃̀̇ḛ̵̣́ř̵͇̳̜̝̀͛Ȃ̵̡̗̊͘͝ẹ̵́r̸̖͒̓̇̋e̸̼͈̋̀͌͆͑h̸̞̺͕͂̀̎̄T̴̰̺̭̤̣̐̏s̸̲̆́͂d̷̲̊͊ŕ̵̘̥̼̝̳o̶̗̣̯̪̐̉͛͑L̷͍̩͇̎s̶̻͙͋̑n̶͎̠̠̔̎͐̆̐o̸̥̅͊̕i̵̤͇̅͐̂s̷̛͓̱̲̋͝ņ̷̛͓̞̞͒̏à̶̢̡̝͖͓̾̓̚͠M̶̧͒ḛ̴̦̣͌h̴͇͑͝T̵̢͎̰̥̋̾͛f̵̛̺͚̹͑͐O̴̦̳̤̒̔̿ë̵͉̟͎͍̹̐̈͝n̸̰̮͌̿̇͊̍ȍ̸̓͋͛̂ͅŃ̸̢̥̈͒̈́̃ḑ̶̟͎̓̎ņ̴̠̹̀̉̑A“
,odaroloC ro ainrofilaC rof srotcepsorp
”̵̰̺̪̉̆w̷̛͎̦͖͚̙̓ő̷͚͇̦̆͑ͅṇ̴͇͔̒̽K̸͙̆̎̇̎͝è̷̘̄l̷̛̗̟̋̽̌̂p̶̞͍͖̩̼̂̽̀̕ö̷̘͍́e̷̱͒͗P̸͙̻̘̎̈́̉̽t̷̪͚̺̻̽̂̆̓p̵̼̲͍͋̌͌̆ȩ̸̹͉̱̒̓͂̎̀͜w̴̜̒́̄̈́ŝ̵͓̐̉̔̔d̷͙̲͇̻̿ṉ̸̨̳̠͕̋̾̎̽͝i̵͇̹̣͒̐͘W̸̫͔̭̅e̴̛̺̲̠͐͊̀͘h̵͍̦̹̗̐T̸͇̻̜̽̈́ͅf̷̍̽͜O̵̧̩̿̽e̷͓̗̥̝͑̈̎ͅn̶̼̝̈́̇̓͊̈́ȯ̵̙̮̜̱̊̈́͋̉N̸̺̤̽̓̆̎͋d̷̼͉̈́͗̂n̴̫̉͊A̷̩̠̿͛w̶̨̡̗̜͌́̔͠o̷͚̹͋͠Ḽ̶͍̩̂̑̀̈́̉ṡ̸̟̗̉g̴̨̯̘͉͖̿̓͑̄͝n̸̺͇̹͍̬̈́i̸̢̲̯̔S̸̬̼͔̠͐͛̾͘͘d̴̛̖͗̾̓n̴̊̀̈́̊̊͜ǐ̷̳̪̍W̵͔̲͙̑͑͐̆ę̵̖͇̀̏h̴̡͈̏́͆̀͝T̸̘̪̯̜̿͝ḏ̴͗̈́̓͐n̸̠̈̓̈̊͜À̶͕͂̕͜͠͝h̶͍͙͇̱̍̽ͅǵ̴̞̌̏į̴͔͎̥͆̔̐̓H̴̨̀s̵̛̺͖̪͖̱̋́͘ġ̴̹͒ǹ̵̨͕́̓͐̒i̴̲̘͒̓̕S̸̝̠̼͂̏̌̂͐d̷͓̑̇̈́n̸͓͊̐̅i̵̲̾̅̓̍W̶͇̓̈́̄̿è̸̡̮̠͂̈́͝ẖ̵̑͒̈́̑̊T̴̢̛̞̻͈̊̉̕͝ͅd̵͇̠̜͐̿̄̉̒ṇ̴̭̓͂̅̓̎A“
.nepo deknilb seye s’efaR ”?era uoy erehW
tahW“ .tah pu-taeb sih deppit ollidamra eht
,potllih a revo ylneddus gniraet tsug a ekil ekops eh
,ylbatciderp dna ylbatrofmoc yrev rehtegot tif taht seceip era eseht
”,hatcod ,htob niod eldnah nac hA“
,niks kciht s’ollidamra na nevig neve
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT
”!si deksa hA noitseuq eht tnatropmi woh dnatsre’nu lla’y ekil dnuos t’nod ti esuaC
”?nwot ni sgniht s’woH
”.lla retfa suoigatnoc t’nia siht fi yas ylthgir t’ndluoc I“
.sretteb dna sredle sti esiwrehto erew taht
”,ninialpxe emos tnaw ’nog si sa eno ylno eht tnia I“ .deppans ynahteB
.gniw s’worc eht koot ynahteB
,dnuor ’sdneirf‘ sih dna sregoR efaR dnes daetsni dluoc yenom
,etoyoc niht llat A
gnireenigne lacisuM
.yrotcafsitas saw siht yltnerappA
.esir txen eht revo tsuj saw nosaer ehT
:enog ydaerla saw liart rehto ehT
,tsaoc eht ot ippississiM eht morf niart nogaw gnol elgnis a neeb evah llew sa thgim ti
,ohcnop deroloc-tsud hguor a ni
,s’yadakceH .srM tem seye siH
.htron eht ot yad a flah
noitagergnoc tsitpab yranoissim a
.reh rof tniop eht ezisahpme ot fooh sih depmats ,noitartsurf s’redir sih gnisnes ,beJ ”!siuL ,sekas dnaL“ ”.thgirla s’yenom eht ,ynahteB ssiM erofeb uoy ’lot I“ ”?ssibroC eteP ruoS ekil nam a rof nikrow deppots uoy emit tsap n’erom s’ti naem taht t’nod tub
.dehgis ynahteB ”?nogaw a tog uoY“
.nam denethgirf a saw elkcarg eht gninrom siht oS
,worc ylredle na saw
”?uoy ’nilia s’tahW“
.won htnom a tsomla rof syad tsom neeb dah eh ekil ,secnef htron eht no tuo saw eiuoL — .retfa
,elkna reh depsarg wap hguor A
.knird rehtona htiw od dluoc hA leef hA“
:ralucitrap t’nsaw ehs tub ,yhw swonk doG ,ot teg ot denimreted eb ot demees ti erehw saw tahT
.erofeb siht ekil cisum draeh reven dah ehS
,won litnu dekramernu wohemos ,rab eht dniheB
”!ffo deklaw tsuj regnarts eht neht dnA“
,htuom reh denepo ynahteB
,sodanrot erew mih denethgirf taht sgniht ylno ehT
.tdleftatS fo nwot eht dna
”.ebyam ,ecalp s’ssibroC ta kcab taht niraeh ekil yeht woh eeS
,ti yas dluow yeht taht esol ot hguone elttil dah dna
.cificaP noinU eht ot
ynahteB ot derrucco ti erofeb rood tnorf eht edam yadakceH .srM taht
,sroyevrus daorliar eht ot klat ot ereh tuo saw ehs—
”eM hguorhT dna ,enO yloH ,eM ni gniS“
— .enoyna rof os did ylerar ehS
”.yenom tog sah sa nwot a fo elpmip siht ni nosrep ylno eht t’nia eH“
woh leef dluoc ehs dna
?kniht ay’d tahW“
stoor kciht nwod tup dah tsop gnidart elgnis a taht hguone lufitnelp neeb dah smaerts esohT
.seirraH nomoloS yb
.ylno ton ,mih ta gnus ohw allef eht t’nerew’T“
,seilppus lacidem gnilles emoc
tdleftatS ni sklof tsoM .hguoht ,mih dellac enoyreve tahw saw tI
,saw eh noserohw eht ekil lleh ot og ot sregoR efaR llet ot
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.taht od ot nogerO ot og d’ti ylbaborP
.yaw eht fo tuo ti teg ,sroyevrus esoht ees og retteB
derevoc erew secaf s’nem eht htoB
”,od htob ew wonk uoY“
.tnemugra railimaf gnol eht gnidaerter fo trohs deppots siuL
”!em rof enod eh sa ytrid sa tib yreve krow rof yap rey koot s’sregoR dewonk I ,htimS orhteJ ,em ta eson rey nwod nikool llac on tog uoY“ ”!esu
nobruob fo ssalg a ta yllatnemirepxe gnippis
”,eman s’lived eht ni tahW“ .nwot drawoT
”.retaw a puc a mih tiG“
”!htlaeh fo erutcip eht s’allef ereh siht reggif nac I sa raF“
,desolc tsomla seye sih tpek ohcnop eht ni retfird eht
.pu saw nus eht emit eht yb
,dehpmurrah aP ”,ris ,neht woN“
,edarap a ni royam a ekil wols gniklaw
ti tif ot yaw a dnif t’ndluoc tub
,saw-ehs-revetahw ,llew ,siht htiw deerga evah dluow ynahteB oga a tnemom A
.raeh dluoc flesreh tub ydobyna erehw os yas reve d’ehs taht toN .dluow reven ehs
,elttil a dehtooms srehtaef reh dna
.swen dab ’na swen doog tog hA ,hatcod lleW“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT    ”.doG ’a tcA‘
”…ma’am no ’niog s’tahw tuob lla ta ’nihtyna wonk uoy n’fI“
”̷̞͉̽̓͂͠͝r̴̮̹͍͍͗͑̿͒̚a̶̧̤͉̼͌̋̅͜F̷̺̪͙̎͑̈s̷͖̺͉͕̃p̵̯͑͝e̷̞̬̓̉e̷̺͍̒w̷̲̥͉̘͛̑͘S̷̤̖͎̳̣̿͝d̵̨͒̽̽̎͝ṅ̸͚̠͉͓̚͜i̴̥̤̫͊W̵̫̭̯͖̋̑e̴̱̗̲̒̍h̴̤̗̠͚̔̽̊͝T̶̻̭͉̝̙̅̈́d̸͔̖͈̦͉̍̅n̴̛̯͔̊͗̽͐ͅȦ̷̛͔̙̫̌ȑ̴̡̡̤͍̻̃͗å̶̡̧͕̞̲̇̀̈́̓é̶͍͕͇̈́̕Ñ̸̰̹̈́ṣ̷͇͇͈̘̈́̉̋ṕ̶̣̥́ȇ̴͓͛̂̽e̴̡̙̅̕̚ẘ̷͓̥̬̾S̶̨̳̐̔d̸̛̖͒̑̓ǹ̶̬̑ỉ̷̡̠̠̙͛̀̆̐Ẅ̷̞̮̠͕́̆̈͘ê̴̩̝̈̉͘ḧ̶̨̝́T̶̫̦̙̯͝ͅd̷̳̈́͂͂̏ń̴̘͙̻̙͚̄̈́͘̚A“
.htob meht derongi retfird ehT
.teef reh no ydaetsnu dekool namow siht emit tsrif eht rof ,nageb ynahteB
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,ot pu uoy saw yltcaz‘ tahW
,ohcnop eht ni ,ereht nwod etoyoc taht ekil—sretfird tsuJ
,yaw niatrec a og ot tnaem erew sgniht spahrep dnA
meht ot kcab teg ylbativeni ro stnerap reh fo flaheb no eb rehtie dluow gniksa yna dna—deksa enoyna fI
,elbats yrevil eht dniheb yella ehT
gnihton naht retteb eb dluow gnihtyna tub evah ot noitcaer tahw aedi on dah elkcarg eht ”,yub t’nod I“
”,taht ekil tfel erew eh ,deppots ti nehW“
snoitseuq yna derewsna t’ndah ehs taht
.daer ot elba eb meht fo eno a ton dluow yeht
.tcatnoc eye ekam ot terref eht teg ot niav ni gniyrt
on ot niog t’nia sa dnal tnacav gnidraoh syad eht yawa deliw lla ew fi enod teg nihton t’ndluoW
,resolc yna saw sroyevrus eht fi kcehc og ot em ’lot aP
,nool a ekil gninnirg dna kcab sih no elgae-daerps gniyl ,hcrop eht no mih ediseb terref eht neewteb deralg ssibroC ”.rissoN“
etaf gnilffab revetahw fo ecaf eht ni neve toN
.worrub a ni alutnarat a ekil
”,gniht eno yas did eH“
.rorroh drawot s’efaR dna
.dedne ti sa reh esaeler gnos eht tlef ehS
.elims guht eht nees reve dah siuL ron ynahteB rehtien sa ,yllacifitaeb
.snoitcif etilop rof ecneitap yna dah reven ehS
”?wonk I dluohs woH“
.repeeknoolas nwot tdleftatS eht osla saw
,meht tsap dna meht fo tuo deruop tI ”̷̺͚̄͌̌̓ý̸͚͓̖̈́̚B̴͈̟̪̀t̸̜̭͇͗͊͘n̵̩̑̿ẽ̶̞͐̃̾̉Ẃ̵̡̠̬̑t̵̬͚͗̀̉̈́͝s̶̫͕̦̈̋̄͝à̶̩͚l̷͖̲̠̲̔̿̓̂͝B̴͈̝͚̞̒̔̃̍é̵͈̈́̓̾̕h̴̯̞̤̔̀͆͑Ṱ̴̔s̴̗͈͓͓̘̓̽̍́͘A̷͚͍͂̂ͅd̴̡̪̦̦̝̀͝ḙ̸̭͇̄̉͊r̵̯̯̘̀̋̿̓̕e̷̼̳̥͒̇͂w̴͚̟̘̰̉͘ͅo̶̭͘C̶͓̞̻͆̋s̴͍̩͈̦̮̀ṙ̸̪͕̾̍̕e̸͕̲̽̿ẁ̴͚̙̣ͅo̵̦͆̾T̶̮̰͉̓́ḱ̵̨͙̘̯͠r̴̨̛̫̺̍̆̕ȧ̸̛͉͈̖͆̔D̷̢̯̺̏̈́̀̒͝e̶̜̽̍̃h̴̗̿̾͛̕T“ .reverof tsol gnieb dna
,gnirats llits saw ehs erehw
,plug elgnis a ni knird reh dehsinif worc eht
,ega nedlog dezigolohtym ydaerla dna feirb sti ni liarT mlohsihC eht no dreh gnidir
,sregoR ot nobruob fo ssalg eht dednah dna
.tluaf reh wohemos saw siht eveileb ot yaw a erew ereht ylno fI
,tennobnus a fo daetsni tah hsinaps
,dnalhcnar gnidnapxe reve sih fo traeh eht ta hcrop nibac sih no syad sih tneps eh nehw won ron
pu gnurps taht tsop gnidart a neeb dah nwot eht fo dees eht yldesoppuS
”onafreuH”—itannicniC ni kcab repeekpohs emos yrram ot nwot tfel d’ehs erofeb ,nwot ni mramloohcs tsal eht—
,eb nac etupsid nwot-llams yttep a ylno sa rettib
,nwot dehcaer yeht nehw sroyevrus daorliar eht pu rettub—
,enO yloH ,eM ni gniS“
aisenodnI ot ecnednepednI morf desaelp ti erehwyna flesti kcuf dluoc liart eht
,flesreh revo htob
,daeh reh tuoba gnirettulf saw epacse eht fo ssenworran tnerappa ehT
”,seidemer tnetap dna scanamla fo royevrup“
kciht os saw ciffart eht nehw syad eht neeb dah esoht
.meht ees ot daeh reh nrut t’ndluoc ehs dnuof ynahteB
”.ris ,ko …ydaerla eW“
,rotcod eht drawot siuL degdun ynahteB
,su fo eerht eht no pu semoc regnarts siht ,dias I ekil
.tsaehtuos beJ nrut ot snier eht dekcilf dna daeh reh koohs ynahteB
rotcod nwot tdleftatS eht ecnis
.htuos ,swolliw eht hguorht edorts dna denrut eh ,drow a tuohtiW
,raw etatse laer nwot-llams yttep a ni dekcol liah yeht hcihw morf ytirucsbo ni ekila sesuoh owt eht
.ekat dluow skcart eht etuor eht tuoba lla ta stnih yna naelg ot dna
.nam tneitap a neeb reven dah ssibroC reteP — ”.sseug I ,cisuM“
wenk nwot eht lla deedni dna
”.sgnis tsuj eh ,nihton yas t’nod eH
ednarG oiR eht morf evird elttac sseldne elgnis a
”?mih htiw seibab neknurd ekil nirebbig owt uoy tnia lleh’ht yhW“ ”.risseY“ ”?lla’y dnA ?oot gnas efaR“
.tnemugra rehtruf rof esucxe na sa taht gnikat ssibroC dna
.nwot edistuo tsuj
”.nrecnoc a sa lla’y ot srucco ti“ ,dereens ssibroC
,tnemom a tub roF
,msaisuhtne dna hsiler tnedive htiw
gniht elbatnuoccanu emos tuB
meht fo tsud ehT
.sserpxe ynop eht no pots a dna
.erom lareves desiar dah deedni dna
,krow s’yad a rof nrab eht ni peels ot ecalp a dna laem a edart ot gnilliw eb ot deneppah reveohw yb laemeceip desiar eb ot ,yob sa ereh mih tfel dah reveohw taht
,ewa drawot denrut
nehw roF .ton did ti tuB
,ytuaeb kcurtsewa dna rorroh neewteb nrot htob erew secaf s’efaR dna siuL ”̸̦̊ȳ̸̖̂͝k̷̨̉̿̊́͂S̷̢̻̼̿͌̋́̕e̷͉̳̓h̴̨̺͙̓T̷̯̞̫͙́̽̒̀f̴͎̳̩͇͍̈̊̄͋O̵̮̓̑̌́̕ė̸͓̤̘̾r̵̡̲̳͔͚̍ú̷͔͓͍t̵̢̤̲̞̼̋̿̇́p̵̣̊̐a̷͍̪̜͖̯̽Ṛ̵͔͖̍͝ḛ̶̉̈́h̴̬̙͖̰͗̅͝Ṯ̶̲͐y̶̼̦͇̿̂̕͝r̸͖̝̞̈́̒͛͗ũ̴̖̜̘̤͌̚ͅF̴̼̮̮̫̈́̌͜s̵̡̡̛̥͆ţ̶̤͎͍̲́̃̔̊̕Į̴̛̘̹̹̾̅̈́̐n̷͈̘͍͍̯̆͝͝a̴̻̯͕̿͝h̷͚̟̤̽̐̅͝T̶̛̛̻́̈́̚l̶͆͝ͅư̸̟͙̼̪̰̈́̈́̆͝f̸̢̦̙̺̋̉͜d̵͕͂a̴͎̋̿̎e̸̱͉̗̎ŕ̸̠D̶̖̫́̈͊͘e̵̲͂́͌͑ř̵̠́ǫ̴̨̠̙͝M̵̨̲̻̰̜͛͘̕͠ḥ̶͓͈̒̓͑̽g̴̹̝͎͈͐̅̎͝i̴͖͍̝̣͛̑̽N̷̢͈̭̐̾́̉͋ẗ̴̨͚́̑̃̌͜l̴͓̻̚ę̴̫̦̥͍̔F̴̛̦̣̽̀y̶̨̲̤̩̌͌̒e̷̞̿͠͝h̵̦̝̖͍̲̋͝͝T̴͎̲͉̥͐̎̔̏̉s̸̭̈́͑͝A̶̢̽͠d̶̟̋̈́̋̏ȩ̴͍̂̈́̄r̶̳̯̳͓͘ͅe̷̗̳̣̬̓̓̒̌͜d̸̢̢̲̺̑̉͝d̸̞̤̩͊͒̅̓̓u̴̞͌̈́̕h̶̨̗̘̓͊S̴̢̖͔̞̟̒͊s̴̭̥̘̀͊̓̈̑n̴̩̽̚o̷̪̞̪̊̋̂́͂i̵͚̞̱͐͂͆s̷̹͚͗͐͝n̸̖̮̙̫̄ả̸̭̱̎̒͐M̴̡̝̝̪͔̈̉̀n̸̖̪̩̈́͋a̴̻̔͐̀͗ĩ̵̧͉͖̘̟̇͊̈d̵̮͖̤̙̐̅ȉ̸̭͕͕͚͕͊̉ş̷̖̥̮̚b̵̥̦̝̈́Ơ̴̭̺̰͉̐͌͂͋e̴̗̤͐͊h̷̝̱̫̲͚̔̉T“
,ylbitpecrepmi tsomla deyaws eH
,ecnattimda rof gnikconk
,gniyalp erew stnerap dias—
eman nwo sih fo egdelwonk sa sgniht hcus fi sa
—kool eht dah eh ,tnemom a teef sih tser ot deppots yltnerappa
”̴̬͆̀̏͝͠t̸̘͖̂̔̚s̴̻͇̠̤̠͑͝e̸̻̯̣͈̐̉͝w̷̝̱̭͇̒̄́ḩ̷̥̬͊̀t̷͚͆̂r̵̲͂ö̴͚͍́̉̅̇͒Ņ̴̺͎̒̚͝k̵̹̤͆̋̑͊̕͜ŗ̸̪̥̬̋̾͐ả̴̖D̷̙̰͆̏ë̸̢̱̼̖́h̷̹̍̐̅̕T̸͎͗͘m̵̘̫̖͍͋̆̕o̴̙͇̳͔̎͂̑̈ṟ̸̔͐͂̎̽F̴̗̜̻͊̎t̷͈̝̮͍͉͋̀n̷̨͖͓̲̎̾̿̈e̸͍͚͊̒̀̚l̶͓̦̈́͛͋̃i̷͇̎̏̾̈́S̷̛̘̺̣͆̐s̵̡͈̺̟͕͑̿̊͝ḛ̴̡͔̥̰̓s̶̢͍̖̊͛̆̋͠i̸̧͖̪͙̊R̴̢̧̝̠̿͝͠d̵̢̦̙̏͐n̶̘͕̤̥̼̽̋̊̋͂i̵͙̮̝͚̲͗̅W̴͉̪̌ė̵̡̳̗̭͇̒̕h̵̖̬͕̪̓ͅT̶̫̉͐͒͋͝d̷̦͚̘̒̍̂̑ṅ̶̮̅̌ͅÄ̸̞̦̣́t̵̨̡͎̮̩̆̀s̴̛͔̖̝̬̹̍̃͒͠e̶̙̻͒̒̄̍ḻ̵̺̣̿̋̍ͅB̴̲̟́̕g̸̪̩͈̪̓̐̒́͠n̴̜͊̑̂̈̎ọ̶̗̙͇̺̈́̿͆̇̚L̸̛̜͈̰̮̈̌̚͜͝e̵̙̫̫͙̎z̸̯͆e̶̤̋̍e̸̢̻͊r̷̥̠̦̭̉̊̈́͆͜͝B̷̤̻͗̚͘ͅȀ̴͎̓̒̀ś̴ͅë̸̱͜m̶̙̗̖͆̔͂̄͂ò̴͉̲̭͂͠C̸̺̺͐s̶͈̱̙͓̆e̶̛̞̜̦͑̓l̶̗̯̜̅̈́ǡ̴̜̼̳́V̸̨̯̝̗̝̌n̵̺̮̹̳̦̂͆͝i̴̲͎̟̒͝a̵̙͎̜͇̞͋̄͆̓͝t̴̤̘̑̌͠n̸̘̙̰̈͠ͅŭ̵̝o̷̭͌̏̓̚M̵̝͙̼̪̏͗̄̓̒d̶̨̬̘͑̋̐̏͠ẹ̷̭̞̐̀̈́͌w̵̠̼̄ô̵̗͎d̸̳̏ą̶̙̘̺͊̌̌̆̀h̶͖̮̬͈̺͆͆̇S̴͖̠̻͕͛͋ͅm̴͒̔̆̔ͅo̷̪̰͌̆͗̓ṙ̶̫̮͙̓F“
.sseug I ,reraeb-elat a gnieb rof hcum erac t’nod I“
”.stneitap ym htiw erefretni ro kcots ym diar ot ereh uoy n’fi dnim ruoy pu ekam tseb uoy“ ,delbmurg roteirporp eht ”,yadakceH .srM“
”,siuL ,ereht gninroM“