pley trohs a evag eillO
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.barc a fo llehs eht ekil rehtegot tif taht
noziroh eht morf tserof eht sdrawot sllor sduolc krad dna
”rednefeD ykS“   :yojne esaelP
.rotor gninnips eht gnissim ylsuolucarim
worra rehtona dekcon eillO
.demaercs iahG
,eye na naht rosnes a fo erom saw ti taht wenk htob iahG dna eillO
.rosnes sti ni degdol daehworra gnol eht sa ,gnilialf smra
mih dnuora pu til skraps erom
.ffilc eht sdrawot ot kcab ydob sih denrut dna delims iahG
.sgniw sih ni niarts eht leef ot trats dluoc eH
.sworra yranidro on erew esehT
.yawa mih gnihsup gnibbats sih fo ecrof eht
,sdrawrof detnirps iahG
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”,fo erac ekat ot melborp erom eno evah llits eW“
,srezzub eht htiw enil ni pu kcab mih yrrac mutnemom sih tel dna
,blub eht fo esab taf eht otni dellird neeb dah seloh ynit eerhT
”.nezod a tuoba tnuoc I  .wonk I“
,mih dniheb morf emac sgniw fo gnitaeb yvaeh A
.dniw eht no yawa welb ylpmis hsa eht
,gnitalp latem detacilpmoc dna egnarts ni derevoc yltsom saw mra tfel s’terref ehT
,semalf eulb fo llab llams a ni dedolpxe daehworra eht retal dnoces A
”!eillO“   .noitcerid gnorw eht ni ylsselesu gniylf worra eht
,rotor gniliaf dna tneb a htiw tfola flesti peek ot gniyrt yletarepsed
,rezzub eht ta sdrawrof dehsur dna deraor iahG
.resolc reve emac llih eht fo kaep ehT
,s’nogard eht sa neek sa ton saw thgiseye siH
,gnol sti fo esab eht raen
.pu hgih siht welb taht dniw gnorts eht dna tnemevom sih yb detatiga
tliuq krowhctap hguor a otni tserof eht morf gnideef
.drawrof detnirps eh sa reworran ylkciuq gnitteg htap eht
.spih sih yb kcab deknay saw ydob sih sa sgnul sih fo tuo decrof saw dniw eht ,ylnedduS
,ria eht hguorht nips rezzub delpmurc eht dehctaw eh sa dereehc dna depoohw eillO
,thgiew eht troppus ot elbanU
”.ylrae os taht ekil erif ruoy esu t’ndluohs uoY
.toh gnirif dna degrahc sekips mra
.efas htob meht peek ot gnivaew dna gnigdod
,temmulp ot detrats eH
,mih llik t’ndluoc resal s’rezzub a wenk eH
,doow gnorts morf edam llits saw tfahs ehT
,dnuorg eht revo lla derettalps ton saw eh taht etaicerppa ot dnoces a koot terref ehT
,mra tfel s’eillO tsniaga detsalb
,worra eht desaeler terref ehT  .ydaets smra sih
,kcilliK yb ”rednefeD ykS“
.eillO tcetorp ot dah eh tub
.dehtaerb nogard eht ”,ti htrow saw tI“
skraps elprup fo hsalf
.deyonna ,ecaf sih fo tuo hsa emos devaw dna
.iahG dias ”,yrros os m’I“
.tunlaw a hguorht ekips niht a nevird dah enoemos fi sa ,esab eht ta llab latem dnuor a dah tub
.redir sih ot kcab dellac iahG
.deraor iahG ”!tohs eciN“
.tluaf ruoy ton s’ti ,yeH“
.kcen s’nogard eht ot elbissop sa esolc sa ydob sih gnigguh ,deyebo eillO
,deddon dna delims eH
yrenihcam fo knalc eht saw erehT
.ria eht ni teef derdnuh wef a dednepsus saw ydob gnilbmert sih desilaer dna
noitisop otni kcab flesmih dehcrul eillO
.latem gnitsiwt fo laeuqs a htiw gnitargetnisid yletelpmoc
,kcalb tnew seye siH
,nus eht ni latsyrc ekil denetsilg
,mih htaeneb welf nogard kcalb evissam a sa
,mih ni seloh gniredloms on dnif dluoc eillO
koob tsrif sih no gnikrow yltnerruc si dna
.yks eht fo tuo rehtona tohs eH
wolg dna muh ot detrats gnirts eht dna
,dednopser eillO  ”,ma syawlA“
srehtaef dna sdaeb fo gnirts trohs A
dnah thgir sih htiW
.dniw gnihsur eht hguorht detniuqs eillO
.htaerb rof detnap dna
,kcab kcen dna daeh sih deraer iahG
.maercs terref eht gnikam
”?erus uoy erA“ ”.ruomra ym tih tI“
,secaf ffilc ykcor
.selacs sih ot thgit no barg dna elbmuf eillO gnikam
.selacs drah s’nogard eht gnittap
,tsalb eht fo egde eht ta thguac erew srehto owT
drawrof mih gniyrrac mutnemom sih ,tpael eH
.wob sih gnipsarg llits elihw
.mih dniheb gniraeppasid dnuorg dilos fo ytefas eht
rotor gninnips a htiw ria eht ni dednepsus
sgel sih ni selcsum eht ,gninrub tsehc
,tnemom a tsuj rof ria eht ni revoh ot demees eh dna yks eht hguorht
wob sih morf gnimooz retfa dnoces a naht ssel dna
.meht sdrawot dekaerts sresal fo yellov tsrif eht sa yaw eht fo tuo gnillor
,llaf ot egakcerw yna neve ton htiW
,gnirts eht tsniaga dehcuot ti sa noos sA
tfola flesti peek ot yaw on htiW
.mih ot kcab dellac iahG ”?ydaer uoY“
.tuo flesruoy erit uoy erofeb ylkciuq siht hsinif ot deen eW“
.stolb eht fo sliated tuo ekam ot trats dluoc
.ytivarg fo llup drah eht tsniaga efil raed rof no dleh terref ehT
edis eht ot devom wodahs ehT
.etarapes ot deirt yeht sa
”,llikrevo saw tahT“
,eno ot esolc welf eH
,meht dnuora elcric thgit a ni deraos iahG
,deeps elbidercni ta tobor eht sdrawot yks eht hguorht dezzihw worra ehT
esac latem erauqs ,egral a saw eno hcaE
emalf fo stej ynit eerht
.stobor gniylf eht fo snoitisop eht deton eh sa dnuora detfihs kcen s’nogard ehT
.redluohs sih tsniaga dellup sworra kciht fo reviuq a fo parts eht dna
,ekans yrgna na ekil dnuora deppihw rehtet epor siH
enots a ekil gnillaf
,sdrawkcab hcrul ti gnikam
.gnab llams a yb dewollof skraps lacirtcele fo kcarc a htiw rezzub a otni hguolp ti dehctaw dna
,blub cimarec eht ni seloh eerht eht fo tuo tsrub
,deifsitas yletelpmoc toN
,rezzub eht fo ydob eht edisni deppop yticirtcele fo skcohs llamS
.dnah wob sih htiw ria eht gnihcnup
.llaf redir sih dehctaw sa demaercs iahG ”!eillO“
.gnorw saw gnihtemos desilaer eh erofeb gnillaf ydaerla saw eH  .gninael dnA
.ekips latem htooms a ni gnidne
”,ti ekam ot gniog t’nerew uoy thguoht I“
,revewoh ,thgil saw tI
.won efas lla erew yehT
,ria rof depsag eillO ,tsiaw sih yb gnignaH ”!uoy tog ev’I“
,sresal dna srezzub eht ot noitnetta esolc gniyap iahG
”.decils tog rehtet yM
,niaga revo dna revo ti gniknahs
.kcab dellac terref eht
deddon iahG  .eillO dehgual
,duht a htiw nogard eht no dednal terref ehT
,llef eh sa eillO tsap delzzis smaeb elpruP
.dneirf sih retfa evod eh dna
,dnopser dluoc eillO erofeB
.gnikoms dna degnis dne eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.yako saw eh taht nogard eht erussaer ot gniyrt
daetsni dna gnirif deppots rezzub eht
.tsaeb eht ot mih derehtet taht epor eht dekcehc eh sa
.thgir saw dneirf sih tub
.nwod derewop sekips eht dna
,yaw sih fo tuo ylkciuq devom stobor eht fo ynaM
.pot eht fo tuo kcuts taht
rettam t’ndid ti neht tub
,epocs latem eht nwod ylluferac dekool terref ehT
.yad suoirolg a saw tI
.hguorht tohs neeb dah tI
.hgual suoirotciv a esool tel tub pleh t’ndluoc iahG
gnisac latem eht otni sregnif sih gud dna tsehc sih ni niap eht derongi eillO
.htaeneb stiucric dna seriw eht gniyortsed dna
.sporc dna sdleif fo
.tsehc sih ot esolc mra gnikahs sih gnidloh ,kcab dellac eh ”!yako m’I“
.deeps gnisirprus htiw nogard eht ta rehtegot devom yeht dna
,ylthgit wob egnarts sih depsarg eH
.erofeb naht retsaf neve drawrof ti gnilleporp
,llih eht pu dluoc eh sa tsaf sa detnirps terref yknal ehT
.yldetcepxenu denrut iahG nehw ecno ylno gnissim
,epocs eht hguorht ylraelc rezzub tsrif eht ees dluoc eH
.wodahs krad eht fo daeha tib elttil a tsuj yats ot flesmih gnihsup
.thgilnus thgirb eht ni gnikniw dna gnitnilg srosnes elprup
ssarg dehsurc ,pmad fo stnirptoof gnivael
,wolley yduag a ni detniap ylhguor saw stobor eht fo hcaE
a saw erehT  .erif ot gniraperp
.meht htaeneb yb gnihsalf sdleif dna revir eht
.redir sih ot kcab dellac iahG
dellac terref eht ”!ahctoG“
.reyarp kciuq a derepsihw eh dna
kcab sih tsniaga sgniw sih gnikcut dnoces tsal eht ta
.deeps ta yawa gnivom dna
,srotor dna sekips mra fo elgnat a ni rehtegot gnihsarc erofeb ria eht hguorht delbmut dna
.meht sdrawot resolc hsur dna
,peets otni yawa deppord
tserof neerg hsul a yb dednuorrus revir a
snolat htob htiw tsiaw ynniks sih dnuora ylmrif eillO gnipsarg
seceip ot rehto hcae gnidderhs
,ruf nworb sih tsniaga deppals dna deppihw cinut htolc siH
.tsaf ylgniyrrow resolc gnitteg mih woleb srezzub eht ees dluoc eh
,selacs s’nogard detcartsid eht tsniaga dednuop sresal sa
.yawa gnillaf dna esool gnimoc latem fo stib llams
.nigeb ot tuoba saw elttab laer ehT
,nwod erom owt tohs eillO
,tluassa eht fo yaw eht fo tuo dna pu welf dna deraor iahG
,raep a ekil tahwemos depahs
.dneirf sih no kcehc ot kcab daeh sih denrut iahG
.stops dnilb wef yrev htiw tobor gnolbo eht gnivael
.stnemgarf toh dna ,skraps
,tfel srezzub erom owt ylno erew erehT
,noitisop lausu rieht otni evom kcen sih gnilddarts sgel eht tlef eh sa noos sA
.erifssorc eht ni nwo rieht fo eno gniyortsed yllatnedicca
,efil raed rof no dleh dna
,tuo denethgiarts iahG
,ecaf sih tsniaga dehsaw noisolpxe eht morf taeh ehT
,eerht nwod nekat ev’I taht smees ti tuB“
,evoba morf meht ta gnimoc saw rezzub lanif ehT  .delbmur iahG
ksuh latem sselesu won eht dehctaw eh sa depoohw eillO  .seceip ot tobor eht fo tnorf eht gnitsalb
,srae sih ni gniraor dniw eht
.tser ot deen uoY  .emoh daeh s’teL“
.liat lufrewop sih htiw tobor wolley eht deppals dna
”,nuf eb dluohs sihT“
sekips eht neewteb deppils eillO
ria dim ni ydob eritne sih nups neht
.emit ni ereht teg ot etarepsed
redluohs sih revo wob egnarts eht gnuls eH
llih yssarg eht fo sedis eht sa
.htuom sih morf erif etihw erup fo llab a dehsaelnu eh raor a htiw dna
.yllufyalp kcab tohs nogard eht ”,ytnelp nwod dewols I“
,dnuorg eht ecaf ot ydob sih gnitsiwT
.eslup eulb tniaf a htiw
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
tsehc sih ni rewop desucof iahG
,rezzub daed won eht morf yawa dna
,eye eht ni rezzub eht debbats ylkciuq dna
.sdeeps elbidercni ta ria eht hguorht drawrof htob meht gnilleporp
,gnihctelf fo daetsni dnA
mih evoba ylneddus nogard eht dehctaw eh sa
.stsalb eht fo niap gnignits eht tsniaga hteet sih gnittirg
deeps pu kcip ot sekorts yvaeh ni gnippalf
.selacs sih ot esolc oot dessap yeht nehw delzzis taht ygrene elprup fo stlob dnuora gnivaew dna gnigdod
,mih teem ot pu dehsur dnuorg ehT
.epols gnisaercni eht etipsed retsaf nar terref eht
,eno sa meht sdrawot devom dna
,dehca llits mra siH
,dnuorg tfos eht no dednuop swap eraB  kcilliK yb
.tluassa tobor elgnis eht degdod ylisae iahG tub ,nogard eht ta nwod dekaerts sresaL
”.taht od uoy erofeb gninraw emos em evig ot deen uoY“
.tohs rehtona pu gninil saw dna niaga tuo wob sih dah ydaerla eillO
won owt eht fo erawa yrev erew srezzub ehT  .thgir saw eH
”.desucof peek tsuJ  .enif m’I“
.eid ro tsaf evom ot dah eh wenk eH
.mih dnuora ria eht ni ssih dna zzif ygrene yldaed eht fo elgnit eht tlef eillO   .terref eht ta tniop ot sekips mra gniwolg sti denrut
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sriahssorc kcalb fo elddim eht ni yltcerid eye ssalg eht gnicalp
,dnah tfel sih ni thgit wob suoicerp sih gnidloh llitS
,htgnel nedoow eht morf flesti dedlofnu epocs latem yldnips a dna
.feiler fo hgis a dehtaerb dna
.ria eht hguorht gniylf osla ,ecnatsid eht ni stolb lareves ees dluoc eh tub
ekal eht revo daerps wodahs krad A
,seigolohtna yrruf suoirav ni dehsilbup seirots trohs lareves dah sah ohw
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
srezzub eht fo eno morf tohs ykcul a sa
.nar eh sa hcum oot nwod mih hgiew t’ndid dna
,kaep sti rof gnicar
.kcen s’nogard eht no ylbatrofmoc flesmih denoitisop dna
”.won efas eb dluohs egalliv ehT
,esac hcae fo edis eht ot dehcatta erew smra owT
.hsa yerg fo duolc a otni tsrub rezzub eht dna
ssalg eht gnirettahs
,blub cimarec llams a
.nogard eht fo eciov gnimoob eht emac
”,daeha pU  .meht ees I“
redluohs sih morf wob sih koot eh sa dennirg eillO
.weiv morf gniraeppasid dna
.lavorppa ni gel s’iahG dettap eillO  ”.looc yrev dnA“
kcilf dilos a wob eht evag eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.no daed thguac saw eno tub ,snoitcerid lla ni gnirettacs puorg eht
.ycarucca decitcarp emas eht htiw ylf ti tel dna
.tfola ydob sti peek ot ria eht ta gnitaeb sgniw sti
.smra dekips rieht demia dna
”,t’ndluow ti dias reven I“
,nellaf dah terref eht woh ot sa
,demaercs eillO ”!ti hsamS“
xob eht fo tnorf eht ni eye ssalg elgnis A
.gninael no tpek eH
.llew sa nirg a ecrof ot deirt tub
.dniw fo hsur gnimocno eht tsniaga flesmih ydaets ot drawrof denael eH
”,elttil a nwod dewols tsael ta evah dluoc uoY“
.tfahs worra eht htiw lellarap
”?ti si ,noititepmoc a s’ti ,hO“
,deppord ylpmis ti
,ria fo slufgnul egral ni dekcus eH
.sresal fo egarrab tnatsnoc eht fo yaw eht fo tuo dna ria eht ni meht peek ot drah dekrow sgniw siH
.raef fo lluf ecaf a dna seye yretaw was dna iahG ta pu dekool eH
.tegrat rieht ta yawa gnirif llits srezzub eht
”!siht od s’teL  .neht thgirlA“
,ti fo pot no won saw tegrat sti taht gnisneS
.esle erehwyna tih neeb t’ndah eh niatrec ot txen saw eh tub
.esrevinu eht fo htaed taeh eht erofeb yltrohs tuo emoc dluohs hcihw
pu derewop stobor gniylf eht sa ygrene fo muh eht dna
.wob sih htiw mia luferac ekat eillO gnittel
.dniw eht no yltneg edilg sgniw sih tel dna
ria fo lufgnul eguh a ni dekcus iahG
.detuohs iahG ”!nwod teG“
,nogard eht ta pu detuohs eh ”!emit tuobA“
worra derewop tej eht yb tfel ekoms fo liart eht dewollof seye siH
.tuo dellac eh ”!srezzuB“
.worra eht fo dne eht ta tas
.noitsuahxe ni depoord
,ria eht ni kcab deleer rezzub ehT
.dnuorg eht sdrawot gninnips tnew tobor dna terref
.trid fo sdolc pu gnikcik dna
.erew srezzub owt tsal eht erehw ees ot edis eht ot tnael eH
.nar eh sa resolc dna resolc gnitteg
,niaga pu ylf ot detrats dna kcab deddon iahG
,iahG delley ”!no dloH“
.snolat gnorts sih htiw trapa ti gniraet dna smra eht yb ti gnibbarg
.deciton ylerab eh tub
,prahs dna gnol saw daehworra ehT  .kciht yrev tub
,tfel eht ot evod dna
.mraws eht hguorht tohs eh sa
.ralloc niht a ekil kcen s’nogard eht dnuora dnuow taht parts rehtael a ot ti dehcatta dna tleb nevow sih morf pilc latem a dellup ylkciuq eH  .kcen kciht
,stobor eht fo eno otni demmals eh erofeb
.eceip eno ni llits saw eh kcehc elbuod ot og tel eillO dna
.eye ssalg eht otni demmals neht
.stobor eht sdrawot kcab dedaeh mih gnirb ot ria eht ni gnitsiwt ylhtooms
.thgil elprup mid a htiw dewolg
.dniw eht ni deppihw wob eht fo pot eht ot deit
”!eno nettog ylno sah nogard yracs ,gib eht dna
dnoces a tsuj rof desufnoc ,detatiseh eH
.reviuq sih morf worra na dellup eh
,kcab sgniw lufrewop sih tsurht eh
.enips sih sdrawot evom ylwols sekips prahs eht was eh nehw depsag eH
sbmil dna kcen siH
eillO resolc tog yeht sA
,tobor eht morf yawa llef eillO
erif etihw fo llab rehtona dehsaelnu dna
”.tseisae eht syawla si eno tsrif eht tuB“
.htaerb rof gnitnap ,terref eht dias
.snolat sih htiw rezzub rehtona fo rotor eht ta gnipiws
.ylivaeh dehtaerb dna dennirg iahG ”,yrroS“
.pu thguac yletelpmoc ylraen
thgir sih htiw tleb sih morf reggad llams a dellup eh
,niaga drawrof deps yehT
.worra tsrif eht dekcon eillO
.niar detnaw hcum fo esimorp eht meht htiw gnignirb
,sdrawpu flesmih demia nogard ehT
.dnah tfel sih ni ylmrif ti dleh dna
.drah oot ezeeuqs ot ton luferac gnieb dna
,no gnidloh regnol on
,nar eh sa tsetorp ni tuo gniyrc
.elddim eht dnuora epirts kcalb a htiw
,terref eht fo woleb dna
,yawa teg ot deirt srezzub ehT
.yllacitnarf delley iahG ”?yako uoy erA“
,yks eulb eht tsniaga neerg fo regnif a ekil saw tI
,yks eht hguorht drawrof tohs owt ehT   ”.iahG ,wonk I“ ”.eillO ,llaf uoy tel reven dluow I wonk uoY“
,ekoms fo duolc a yb dednuorrus
,woleb teef dnasuoht A
.ria fo hsur duol eht otni
,sthgis rieht ni nogard tfiws eht peek ot gniyrt elihw erif ot gniunitnoc
mih woleb raf tserof eht ni revir eht rof demia eH
,semalf eht yb demusnoc saw ti sa toh etihw denrub tobor ehT
,kcilliK yb ”rednefeD ykS“ saw sihT
.tleb nevow sih hguorht ylluferac delruc swalc s’iahG fo eno
,mraws eht fo suelcun eht ot resolc reve gnideeps saw iahG
sertem wef a evod nogard ehT
”!krow dluow ti uoy dlot I“
,deffuh nogard ehT
,ylhsrah ton tub thgirb enohs nus ehT
tnemom a ylno ylduol erows eH
,desaet terref eht
.llef eh sa reggib gnitteg woleb tserof eht dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ruomra sih ffo gnitehcocir
.wolg eulb emas eht ni pu til daeh worra eht
,og tohs sih tel dna niap ni tuo deirc eH
,yks eht morf pord
,sgel gniniarts sih otni rewop erom elttil a tsuj gnicroF
tfel eht ot saw  erutaerc suomrone eht litnu llih eht fo egde eht revo dna
”,em hctac ot gniog t’nerew uoy thguoht I ,ereht tnemom a roF“
.selacs kcen s’nogard eht gnibbur ,eillO dias ”!sknahT“
.rehtaew eht gnirimda tsuj naht ksat tnatropmi erom hcum a dah iahG dna eillO tuB
”.llaf em tel reven d’uoy wonk I“