”yppuP wonS“   yojne esaelP
.flesym deklim ylluf dah I ,nemes fo trups os ro htfif eht retfA
.devirra I erofeb gnol ehcadaeh a dah ylekil ehs ,niaga nehT
srevol ym rof sdrac yadiloh gnitseretni emos ekam dluoc I teb I
,retsaf neve htgnel ym pmup ot em detavitom ylno snoitanihcam dwel ym nopu ezag reH
.pu ssap ot nuf hcum oot yaw ekil sdnuos wons eht ni dekan gniyalp fo aedi eht
ecalperif til eht ot txen thgir pu tes riahc a dah ydaerla ehS
,ylrae emoc ot llaf rof yarp I
.rewol decnalg seye reh deciton I nehw
.ylleb ym derevoc taht ecnesse etihw emas eht htiw gnippird dnah ym
.meht dnuora seirots trohs gnitirw dna
.flesti fo dna ni elssah a t'nsi ti naem t'nseod taht ,llitS
,kcoc ym fo daeh eht morf detpure diulf ykcits
.aedi eht redisnocer dluohs ehs taht detsisrep dna denilced ylivaeh I
,denihw ehs ",eromina ti ekat t'nac I ,yakO"
a fo hcum woh em dednimer stuocS ni spirt gnipmac retniw fo snezod dna esnes nommoc ,revewoH
,tluda nworg-lluf a m'I taht woN
elohw reh evig dna seod nottoc ekil tsuj
.tey dewolp t’nerew sdaor eht ecnis yawyna revo emoc t’ndluoc I ,sediseB
.thgis eht fo gnimoclew yrev eb dluow ecilop nwot eht tbuod I ,did ti fi neve dna ,hctorc ym ro stsaerb ym laecnoc t'nseod taoc retniw yM
,tew steg ti nehw taeh niater ot ytiliba sti sesol ruf woh reh ot nialpxe ot detpmet saw I
tsuj ni tuo og dluoc I tub
,detroter I "!esoprup no taht od t'ndid I ?!tahW"
,neht dna won yreve tub
.spils naiduerF htiw sdrow reh revo gnilbmuf ,emit eritne eht gnirats saw ehs yllautneve litnu ,regnol tog secnalg eht dnA
,tib a pu sgniht gnikahS
.mraw dna ecin eb llits d'I dna fracs a tub gnihton gniraew ereht tuo klaw ylbaborp dluoc I ,kceH
.detupsid I ",kcid ym dekil uoy thguoht I tub ,wwwA"  .denihw ehs "!taP
,raey yrevE !gniworg gnikcuf
,esle ydobemos no nedrub eht gnittup thgir leef t'nseod tsuj ti tub ,pleh rof dneirf a ksa dluoc I ,eruS
,pu kcab strats loohcs litnu od ot gnihton dna kaerb retniw gnirud emit siht lla htiW
,deksa I "?rewohs ruoy esu I fi yako ti sI"
.lla ti od annog m'I ,nemwons dna slegna wons gnikam ot eugnot ym no sekalfwons gnihctac morF
,msidun gnivlovni tra gninoissimmoc syojne taht retirw yrruf a si ohw
,dloc eht ot erusopxe hcum taht morf aimrehtopyh nettog t'ndah ehs elcarim a yleniuneg saw tI
.renob a tsuj saw tI
.namow rehtona dna dneirfyob reh htiw oga skeew wef a dah ehs emoseerht a yllacificeps
.detixe I sa ssa neerg ym fo weiv tsal eno icreP evig dna liat ym esiar ot erus gnikam ,moorhtab eht ot yaw ym edam I ,noissimrep reh htiW
.tcaf ni ,em deticxe yllaer
”yppuP wonS“ saw sihT
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer ,eugirtaP yb
taeh remmus taht
,roolf s'icreP revo lla gnimmuc diova ot sa os ,ydob ym sdrawot drawpu kcid ym detlit I
ylimaf ym htiw aococ toh fo spuc gniknird ot drawrof kool I
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.icreP ot gninrut erofeb ti dewollaws dna sregnif ym morf diulf mraw eht dekcil I
.reh tuoba derac llits I
,dnuora semoc rebotcO ecno esuaceb
,gnisserac yltnerruc saw I erusaelp fo rallip eht gnitautnecca ,drawrof spih ym detsurht I
,snoitca ym deunitnoc I oS
".evots aht evoba drabbuc ad ne s'tE ?eseewP ?oot ,aet neewg emos em ekam osla ajduhk ,haY"
.ehtaerb smra ym tel dna ydob ym ffo ti dils I ,smra ym etatirri ot gnitrats eidooh ym fo srebif eht htiW
,ti ot dnim ym tup yllaer I fi ,kceH
.elbaliava saw taht noitpo eno saw ereht ,noitautis tnerruc ym no gnitod ,llitS
su retsep ot edistuo sgub fo kcal latot ehT
.yroeht ni nuf dednuos yldettimda hcihw
,yllarutan taoc rieht dehs t'nseod ohw eldoop a sa tub ,rehtaew hcaeb tcefrep dna snoitacav loohcs htiw remmus eht yojne elpoep tsom wonk I ,eeS  .ruf ym
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.htimS niatnuoM eht
…dna tsaortips-esrever tnecifingam a ni htob ecneirepxe tog ehs woh dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.regnol tib elttil a tsuj tsal ot noitasnes eht gnitnaw yletarepsed
,rednaw ot dnim ym dewolla dna seye ym desolc I
.ma I sa gnimoorg htiw decneirepxe sa ton er'yeht fi yllaicepse
.elttek eht fo tuo eltsihw ot nageb maets ,euc no fi sA
spotesuoh morf gnignah selcici
snaginanehs dekan fo stros rehto dna msinoitibihxe
eht reh evig ton yam I
,htaed ot reh evol I ,naem I
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
pots t'now tsuj riah ym esuaceb
.wons eht ni saw ehs gnol woh reh deksa I ,ni em tel ehs retfA
.xamilc ot resolc flesym hsup ot leuf sa seiromem eseht gnisu ,tsiaw eht woleb dekan edistuo deklaw ev'I semit ynam eht ot
?thgir ,oot ,enim fo ttub siht ekil uoY"
.redluohs ym revo reh deye I sa dnah ytpme ym htiw skeehc ym fo eno gnibbur ,liat ym detfil dna dnuora nups I ,deifsitas tey toN
,tiartrop a rof riahc egnuol a no esop dluow ledom edun a yaw emas eht edis ym no yal ,roolf reh no tuo flesym deyalps I ,dias taht htiW
,ylyoc dekoj I ",em rooP"
ressik taerg yllaer a saw namow rehto eht woh dna
.tuo dellac I "?aet ruoy ni gnihtyna tnaw uoy oD"
flesym derusaelp yldehsabanu I elihw rueyov evissap eht fo elor eht gnikat eno eht won saw msinoitibihxe fo syoj eht em thguat tsrif ohw eldoop ehT !cinori woH
".won taht did uoy fi kcis em teg thgim uoy tub ,detnaw uoy lla ti deknaps dna ti dedaenk ev'dluoc ylbaborp uoY
.srehtaef ym tsuj ni dekool I woh dekil ehs taht em dlot ecno dah ehs woh llacer tub pleh t'ndluoc I
,demialcxe icreP "!parc yloH"
;)ecitslos eht yojne I snosaer eht fo eno eb ot neppah seod taht fi neve( syadiloh eht tsuj naem t'nod I dnA
…em deticxe yrots reh ,llew
.tnemom eht ezies dna ti fo egatnavda lluf ekat I erus nmad ekam ot gniog m'I
.peets aet eht tel dna spuc ruo deruop I ,taht htiW
.dekoj I "?em rof saw ti sa uoy rof doog sa ti saW"
.sroodtuo yllihc eht ni emit gnidneps retfa
,hcihw fo gnikaepS
.saw taht aedi elbirroh
.reh fo tuo detnaw I noitcaer eht nettog gnivah ,elims a kcarc tub pleh t'ndluoc I
".won ti fo erac ekat t'nod I fi srehtaef ym fo tuo teg ot hctib a eb annog si sihT"
.retsum dluoc ehs eralg htaed tseilgu eht em gnivig yb dednopser ehS
,ecalp gnimoorg lanoisseforp a ot og I fi dna flesym yb ti od ot yssem oot yaw steg dna gnol oot yaw sekat tI
.erusaelp fo dlohserht ym gnihcaorppa yldipar
.elkcuhc llams a tuo gnittel ,deppiuq yllautneve ehs ",kcid hseiN"
.pleh ym tuohtiw hguone elbaresim ydaerla saw ehs raelc saw ti ,togips ytsur a ekil gnippird eson reh dna mrots a pu gnihguoc sgnul reh htiw tub
.em ot niap etulosba na si
.xamilc ot resolc flesym gnirb
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.retniw devol syawla ev'I  eugirtaP yb
.reh fo erac ekat dna
.ecalperif eht otni gol a werht dna no kcus ot egnezol a reh evag I .pleh dluohs cniz eht ,esle lla rof sA .tisiv
.tnemtaert 'hcuot t'nod tub ,kool'
.deneppah ti revenehw em morf yawa ecaf ot hguone suoreneg saw ehs tub ,ecnetnes-dim hguoc ro ezeens d'ehs ,yllanoisaccO .cte
.ffo evots eht tuhs I dna raewrednu ym pu dedlof I ,etsah htiW
.kcoc denedrah-won ym ta gnikool ,dedlocs ehs ",esaet 'nigguf uoY"
.sehcnarb eert dna sfoor pota derehtag wons etihw dna
eht reh evig llew sa thgim I neht
.raey txen litnu meht no regnif a yal t'nod dna resserd ym fo kcab eht otni srettuc zzub dna srossics ym worht I
,draykcab reh ni thgif llabwons dekan a evah dna ecalp reh ot revo emoc ot detnaw I fi em gniksa eulb eht fo tuo em detxet ehs ,yadretsey tsuj ,elpmaxe roF
"!ti hcuot neve t'ndid I !nwo sti fo dnim a sah tI"
.elbat eht no elip a ni nwod ti yal dna tnemrag hcae dlof yltaen ot erus edam I ,gnihtolc fo elcitra yreve htiW
.sseldrager reh no noisserpmi na tfel I tsael ta ,lleW
.moor gnivil reh ni thgir
.rettiwT dna ytiniffAruF no ylniam dnuof eb nac eH
,tnemtaert 'detnioppasid tsuj ,dam ton m'I'
ot derehtob I yhw s'tahT
.dekan em nees reve dah ohw nosrep ylno eht saw ehs ,emit eht tA
!ydob ym revo lla
.ecalperif eht yb teknalb a ni pu depparw saw I fi sa yzzuf dna mraw sa tsuj leef dna seohs dna
.stsrub lareves htiw hcamots ym revo lla gnirettalps
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.derewsna icreP "!uyk gnat oN"
,eugirtaP yb ”yppuP wonS“
retirw wollef yb detide saw yrots sihT
,ailatineg ym ot resolc reve gnidils ,ylleb ym gnola nwod dnah a gnikans
.eussit a otni gniwolb erofeb detnemmoc ehs ",oot ,kcis uoy 'niddeg no nalp nud I .flezym tad vu erac ekat nac ekil ton z'ti ,lleW"  .dekrims I "?icreP ,ti tuoba gnihtemos od ot em tnaw uoy oD"  …reh gnitcartsid pots ot noitcere ym detnaw ehs fi tub ,reh gnisaet pots ot em dlot evah yam icreP
"!drutzzab ykcoc uoy ,em no sid nip tnuD"  ".yrots xes yzarc ruoy ot gnitcaer ylbaborp s'ti ,gnihtyna fI" ,dednefed I ",gnihtyna gniod ton m'I !uoy dlot I"  "!zzeY"
.yawa kool ehs did ron ,flesym htiw gniyot morf em pots ot gnihton did ehs ,msicitirc reh etipseD
,stsaerb s'icreP htiw deyalp reve I tsrif eht morF
!sruoh owT ?rewsna reH
,snoitca reh htiw ma I sa yppahnu sA
.ti fo shtnom eerht elohw eht tuoba gniklat m'I
htiw og ot evah dluow I
.deohce eninac ehT "!zzij attol assaD !hguod ,eelzuoireS"  ".draeh ev'I oS"  .detaeper icreP "!zzij attol assaD"
,ydob ym no edam I ssem eht gnirimdA
.srevihs eht tabmoc ot gnitaeh eht pu denrut evah tsum icreP
.retaeht dwel a fo tca driht eht ekil erif eht fo thgil eht yb eno fo ecneidua ym gniniatretne
,reh ot ynnan gniyalp yad ym dneps ot gniog m'I fi tub
.flesreh ot gniklat reh draeh I ,moor eht tfel I sa esuaceb ,eciton ot daeh-nwo-reh-ni oot neeb ev'tsum ehs ,revewoH
.ruf ym ni em fo sotohp roodtuo hsilyts wef a ekat neve ro ,htiw thgif llabwons edun a evah ot revo enoemos etivni dluoc I ebyaM
eno siht piks esaelp
,tuo reh tae ot tog ehs nehw detsat yssup s'elamef wollef reh suoiciled woh gniliated saw ehS
.tew ylsuoires em gnitteg si enola thguoht ehT
,em ekil naiva thgiewrevo na ni was ehs tahw wonk t’nod llits I
.stnemevom s'dnah ym pu deps dna
.semitemos icreP eveileb t'nac I
.moor gnivil eht ni tif gnihguoc a otni gniog yppup kcis eht raeh dluoc I ,retaw htiw elttek eht dellif I sA
"!gnitcawtsid ood ztI"
…esoht ekil serutcip fo tuo
revo emoc ot em deggeb yllacitcarp ehS
.noitcerid ym ni ekat elbuod a did ehS
.emit ni tsuj reh degdod I tub
.dah ev'I serutnevda dwel eht lla tuoba gnicsinimer
?ehcadaeh a hcus reh gnivig noitcere ylsaem eno saw woh tub ,reh esaet ot tuo tes I ,eruS
gnihtemos seod dna seog ehs
,erif eht yb pu deldduh eninac eht was I ,ni gnikeeP
:scipot lausu eht derevoc eW
,retniw evol I yhw snosaer eht lla fo tuo nosaer eno ylno esoohc ot dah I fi ,revewoH
"!zzij attol assaw tad ,nmaD"
,etihw dna tsrub dah sllaw ym ,retal sdnoceS
.hcus sa reh dlot I dna
!emoc ot ytinutroppo eht rof tiaw yldrah nac I
.erofeb taht deirt reven ev'I ,ylsuoivbO
.ydob ym fo ffo pird sehctolb etihw eht fo yna tel ot ton luferac ,teef ym otno kcab flesym gnihsup ,ffo ti devaw I ",thgir lla ,thgir llA"
.noitabrutsam ym fo weiv retteb a rof drawrof gninael reh htiw
,kcid ayeb tnuD"
.dnatsrednu t'ndid I
,lla ta emit on nI
,erusaelp eht ot flesym tsol I erofeB
,snaej ,trihs-T a
!wons eht ni dekan ssa-kcub sruoh owT
tilc reh no tlef eugnot s'werdnA taerg woh tuoba liated enif otni gniog pu dedne ehS
,pit eht ot esab eht morf rebmem ym gnibbur
.ti edih ot od dluoc I hcum t'nsaw yllaer ereht ,ecalperif eht yb ni gnittis saw I noitisop gnilaever eht gniredisnoc dnA
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,mraw leef ot sreyal nopu sreyal no tup evah elpoep emoS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ssa eht ni reh setib dna kcab semoc ti nehw delffab yletelpmoc eb ot yticadua eht sah dna suolucidir yletulosba
.trohs ruf ym tuc stnerap ym tel t'ndluow I esuaceb dik a sa semit ynam os ekorts taeh nettog ev'I
.deggurhs ehs ",daeha oG"
.retniw evol I snosaer eht lla tuoba koob elohw a etirw ylbaborp dluoc I
.niav ni lla saw ti tuB
.elddufeByssaB dna
keew rehto yreve tihsllub siht htiw laed ot evah yllausu I dnA
ym evah I ,gnizeerf woleb steg ti emit eht yb dna ,worg ot snigeb ruf ym ,pord ot snigeb erutarepmet eht sA
?drager hgih hcus ni dleh ehs tahw reh yned ot I saw ohw dna ,derevoc llits erew icreP ot gnidrocca ’stessa tseb ym‘ ,llitS
".'nimoc sid nees ffuduhs I"
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
yrrebnikceH sucraM
.etats larutan ym ot flesym derednerrus dna roolf eht ot sreward ym deggut I
.ecnartne dnarg ym ekam ot ydaer ,dnah hcae ni aet neerg fo gum toh gnipip eno dah I
".kcis os t'nerew uoy fi ti htiw nuf fo ytnelp dah ev'dluow uoy teb I"
,ecalperif eht fo tnorf ni nwod gnittis ,dedecnoc I ",thgirla ,thgirlA"
.mrots a pu gnizeens s’ehs won dna yawyna edistuo tnew ehs gniyas em detxet ehs ,yadot esuaceb ,netsil t’ndid ehs ,yletanutrofnU
.noisiv larehpirep reh ni ylamona neerg thgirb eht deciton ehs litnu ,elihw eht lla flesym gnitneserp
".elbatrofmoc flesym teg tsuj em tel woN
?cilbup ni tuo og ot evah I syas ohw ,niaga nehT
.raey eht fo shtnom remraw eht rof flesym moorg ylreporp ot troffe dna emit eht ni tup ot erus ekam I
,klat 'detnioppasid tsuj ,dam ton m'I'
fo thgis lufituaeb eht htiw syad wons eht evol I
.tey gnimmuc enod t'nsaw I ;dias ehs tahw s'taht kniht I ,tsael tA  "!zzij attol assaD"
,reh sdrawot yaw ym edam I ,yltneliS
.trihsrednu eht neht ,snaej eht neht ,skcos eht emac taht retfA
.snosaes rehto eht revo egatnavda eguh a osla si
,flesym no psarg ym desaeler I
sesunis reh dna dedaj seye reh ,steknalb ni dereyal dna eborhtab a ni pu depparw ,em rof rood eht gninepo retfa deteerg ylkaew ehs
ycreC yb edam tra eht yb deripsni saw dna
.ydob eritne ym gnirevoc retaews retniw nwo
.naom a tuo tel dna seye ym gnisolc erofeb noitcerid reh ni dekniw I
.spitregnif ym htiw dor ytaem eht gnigassam ,snoitartsinim ym nageb I ,tfahs ym gnibbarG
,dnoces hcae htiw gnilggurts
!hpmmM !meht fo eno htiw wons eht ni evol ekam dluoc I ,retteb neve ro
.tnuocca knab ym ni yenom eht lla pu stae ti
.elbat nehctik eht rednu nwod meht tes dna seohs ym ffo dekcik I
,revewoh ,ylbativenI
.edisni gniklaw ,deohce I ",olleH"  .mgelhp fo lluf
.emit htruof a dna ,emit driht a neht dna ,emit dnoces a deneppah ti ,nehT
.emoseerht reh tnuocca citore reh htiw deunitnoc dna seye reh dellor icreP
.no kcab sehtolc ym tup dna og yletaidemmi t'nod I fi em esucxe os ,srehtaef ym tub gnihton dekool I woh dekil uoy taht erofeb dias evah uoy tub"
,dnabtsiaw ym otni sbmuht ym gnikcitS
.sgel derevoc-mined ym gnola gnitrofmocsid emas eht leef ot nageb I ,eidooh eht dedlof I sA
.noitpecrep s'eldoop detrevrep eht ot stessa ym gnitneserp
.ydob ym tuoba elbatrofmoc tol a leef em edam taht yas reh gniraeh tub
.saw esuoh elohw eht mraw woh em no denwad osla ti ,evots eht no elttek eht gnicalP
,stiolpxe lauxes ruo fo cipot eht otni detfird noitasrevnoc ruo
.noitapicname elitxet rieht gniyojne ,ylleb dna smra ym gnola sdnah ym nar I
,stnemevom ym gniunitnoc elihw eht lla
,sgum eht fo eno reh gnidnah ,deilper I ",sknahT"
".flesym ti fo erac ekat ot evah tsuj ll'I sseug"
gnihcti pots-non fO !syaD !owT
,ytisoiruc deye-ediw htiw decalper neeb dah ecaf reh no niadsid kcom fo lwocs ehT
,ylyoc detats I ",hguoht ,ti htiw yalp t'nac uoy emahS"  ".mucliw eruY"  ".tib a pu uoy reehc thgim thgis eht thguoht I"
.renroc eht ni eninac eht ta dekeep dna eye na denepo I
,tuo era stnerap elihw swons reve ti fi ,ti selttes tahT
.llew sa sehtolc ym ffo gnikat dna moordeb reh otni em gnillup erofeb kaeb eht no ssik deticxe na htiw tius yadhtrib reh ni em teerg d'ehs ,yad rehto ynA .lrig rooP
,sdnab knup lacol
.noitasrevnoc lausac otni deuges yllautneve ew ,nwod delttes dna reh gnisaet dehsinif I retfA
",'nimoc ref uyk gnaT …olluH"  .esuoh reh ot yaw eht no erotsgurd eht morf cniz emos pu gnikcip ,did I tahw yltcaxe s'taht ,detlas dna dewolp yllanif sdaor eht dna pu deraelc rehtaew eht htiw ,oS
.dereffo I ”?uoy rof od nac I esle gnihtynA“
,seye reh gnillor ,dehgis eninac ehT
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tolp elttil suoived a dehctah I ,dnim ni noitulos suoivbo yrev a htiW
.dias ehs ",mraw em peek esop's zuw taoc retniw hum tuB"
.ydob rewol ym ot gnitniop ,deksa I "?taht naem uoY ?tahW"
.daetsni esu dluoc I taht draykcab lanoitpecxe yltcefrep a evah I
.syad owt elohw a detsal ti emit eno ,ekoj oN !hgU
.htraeh eht morf gnildnik srebme eht ta gnizag
.krow ta htob er'yeht elihw wons ll'ti yad eno ebyam tub ,em gnihctac stnerap ym fo eussi eht s'ereht ,esruoc fO
,s'08 dna s'07 eht morf smlif tluc ,sesruoc egelloc
.meht fo snezod nees ydaerla ev'tsum icreP
,kcab flesym dloh ot deirt I sa denaorg I
.gnihcti moorg-tsop eht htiw detrats em teg neve t'nod dnA
,sukcut eht no em taws ot deirt dna em ta tuo dnah a dehcaer yppup kcis ehT
,sfeirb-rexob ym ot nwoD