.wons fo redwop thgil a ni derevoc kcor erab ot no uoy deppord koot tsuj uoy elbmuts drawkcab tahT
,etuor ne uoy ot raed si taht gnihtyreve htiw tcatnoc gnikam ,sgel ruoy neewteb
?uoy era ,won tcefrep toN
mih ecaf dna dnuora nruT
.uoy fo tnorf ni ylno si dloc ehT
.eciwt knilb seye ruoY   .ekawA
,sniol sih ni gnislup gninrom eht fo doolb eht leef uoy ,erom elttil a evom uoy sA
meht fo 563 evah ll'eh tniop emos tA
.lanoisseforp tub
.dniw eht gnihctac era snoitadnuof eht dna
dloc eht ni gnirevihs deldduH
— noitcaer eht wonk uoY
;sgel ruoy fo sdne eht ta sgep gnileefnu fo riap a evah tsuj uoy rehtehw ro tsixe llits yeht fi rednow uoy gnol os rof dloc neeb evah teef ruoy
!reverof nur dluoc uoy tlef uoY
.tnemom a rof ffo deppord tsuj evah tsuM
.liart eht gnisu fo daetsni
,ytisnetni gnippop-eye htiw uoy serutparne tI
.eno tcefrep eht er'uoY
:but-toh gnitalumits sti dna anuas sti htiw ,nibac eht ,ecalp lufrednoW
.hguoht ,ssenhguor siht rof deen on s'erehT
,ti dias uoy kniht tsuj uoy spahreP
.eulb etaciled a si smlap dna sdap ruoy fo niks ehT
?spahrep ,nibac eht ni mih teem uoy diD
;sregnif dna smra ruoy
,pmots dna mriuqs uoy ekam ot sbmil ruoy hguorht etarbiv seldeen dna snip
!noitaroloc ruoy fo duorp os syawla erew uoy dnA
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
taoc trohs ruoy fo ytuaeb evisserpmi eht dna gnidahs ruoy wohs ot tiaw t'ndluoC
.redneT .gniraC .suoituaC
.ysword elttil a tsuj er'uoy ,tcaf nI
… eciffo eht dna anuas eht dna ytic eht fo elbmut dna hsur eht rof tlep tcefrep eht evah uoy taht uoy sllet edirp ruoy teY
.ekatsim yb retnirp sih no yllanoisacco dna ,4 .loV gnaF ni
si yrots s’yadot dna
:ssendekan ruoy revo smaor wap siH
;lla ti fo ytidigirf ffup-nottoc eht ni gnitacoffus
.lufrewoP .citnagiG
.ruf etihw esned ni derevoc ,lufrewop dna gib s'tI
.uoy evoba gnirewot :eguh s'eH
.ruoloc ytterp a si eulB
;uoy morf hcterts-flah a dna hgis yratnulovni llams a gnitcele
.tsehc sih otni uoy gnillup
dniw eht ni yawa welb gnidliub eht spahreP
,trops rehguor otni s'eh ebyaM .peed dna
,psirc fo xim gnillirht a
sserac s'revol A .hcuoT
.elttirb os si elims ruoY
.esnes ekam ot evah t'nod
.evil uoy hcihw ni drib eht morf srehtaef eht gniwolb ,leurc os sdnuos tI   .dniW
,snirg raeb ralop ehT   .psag dna
... yks eht ni srewolf gnirps das morf sraet ytterp fo ruoloc eht s'tI .sraeT
.xelpenic eht ta seivom gnihtyrevE lautriV repuD-repuS seR-hgiH eeD eerhT cipocSamaronaPameniC esoht ekil
,reucser ruoy fo ecaf eht ot pu kool ylwols neht
;keehc ruoy ot spit-rae ruoy morf
.drib a edisni ton ,tnemtrapa na ni evil uoy — tuB
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sussateM yb
.ffuts gniredduhs taht lla deppots evah ot mees uoy ,oN
.ylevol s'eh mih llet ot yrT
,ylision snway dna rits uoy sleef eH
,uoy ekaw ylniatrec dluow taht noitca tnetsisni na
.dneirf tseraed ruoy ekil eroc ruoy otni hcaer ot ti wolla uoy dna
.niaga yawa edaf uoy sa ,elims uoy
?tnet a otni yaw ruoy dnif uoy did htrae no woH
.ti rebmemer uoy ,peY
.htap ylbbub ,ylbbow ruoy wollof t'ndid
.sdliw eht ni enivar elttil a ni peed ,senip eht gnoma ,liart eht ffo
,swap ruoy fo hcaer fo tuo tsuj gnag eht ees nac uoY
.ssen-erac-yam-lived ruoy :ssenwar ruoy :dael ruoy wollof ot meht derad uoY
... sekaw eh nehw dnopser nac uoy os
.semitemos taht od uoY
.tcatnoc gnillirht fo stol dna ,oot seidob toH
:nirg ediw a htiw enoyreve llet uoy
.sbmil sih gnihcterts dna gnitrons
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.muiriled semoc nehT
,taht ekil og hself ruoy edam taht saw ti revetahw od nac uoy fi rednow uoy elihw
.noissergga eht nwod enot ot
.elttil a ehca uoy sekam taht yaw a ni enips ruoy gnidneb
— elap si ruf ruoY
... derit ... dnuora ... nrut
.ecaf ruoy ot kcab yaw eht lla semoc wap siH
?uoy lliw ,niaga wons ees ot tnaw reve ,reven lliw uoy ,ytic eht ot emoh nruter uoy nehW
.savnac hcuot dna wap eerf ruoy tuo hcaer uoy ,ylwolS
.niks ruoy sserac ot ruf ruoy hguorht snur wap eltneg A
.retaw ymaof ,toh dna ria dloc-eci
,sregnif roop ruoy sa evitisnesni sa si ,revewoh ,liat suoicerp ruoY
.yks raelc dna srewolf gnirps ekiL
”nI dewonS“ saw sihT
,esab-liat ruoy ot tsomla kcab dna
?gniht dab a ro gniht doog a s'taht fi llacer uoy oD
.ruf fo gnirevoc sseltniop rieht rednu hsiyerg
.rettam t'nseod ylbaborP
,uoy gnieb uoy ,yllarutaN
.nus tresed a ekil uoy nihtiw stsrub htmraw sa elims uoY
.dnopser t'ndid uoy
.tfird dna ,tfird dna ytip-
.steehs nitas eht egamad ll’eH
.emoh mih thguorb evah tsuM
.trats a htiw seye ruoy nepo uoY   .ezoD
,ten.ytiniffaruf no yhpargotohp sih weiv dna
,enizagam nocorhtnA eht ni deraeppa sah krow siH
.selbmur eh ",kcab emocleW"
— ecanruf a ekil s'eH
.uoy gnildduc ,uoy htaenrednu rehtona dna
.hgiht ruoy otni gnisserp
.noitisop elbatrofmoc erom a ot evom ot yltneg rits uoY
uoy htiw gnihgual
.kcab si muiriled ehT
.rerimda ro revol evitcepsorp yna ot
— 'esruoc fo esu lanosrep rof'
kcab emit emos gnitirw detrats sussateM ,dnalerI fo tsew dliw eht ni desaB
;daeh ruoy fo pot eht otno kcuts yalc fo spmul ekil srae ruoy
.moc.sussatem no ro
,hgual uoy dna hgual yeht
?gnirevihS .tlep ruoy tsuj ni
.siht ekil gnihtyna kool sdneirf esolc ruoy fo enon sa ,hcnalb uoY
,dwel gnieb ton s'eh esilaer uoy wohemoS
.kcalb tej era sregnif eht fo dne eht no swalc ehT
.swalc ruoy dniheb tsuj
,ylleb ruoy revo mra na s'erehT .nediw seye ruoY
.peels ngief dna elzzum ruoy nepo
.tlep ruoy morf dehsug maets dna ocol a ekil gnitnap erew uoY
,oot eulb era seot ruoY
.spil ruoy morf naom ekil-kaeuqs a gnicrof ,ydob ruoy slemmup eh sa
.daeh ruoy gniwollip ,sexob kcalb dna der lla
,bmun swap ruoy dna elzzum ruoy
,feihcsim rof seert ywons eht hguorht ni gnidaeh ,deirt uoy oS
.uoy retteb meht evah t'ndluow uoY
,yawyna uoy dnif ot gniog ton er'yehT
,sedaf niap eht ,kcab swolf doolb eht litnu ,hteet ruoy gnittirg
?enoemos htiw deb ni uoy erA
.uoy ekil tsum eH .syartS
.won dna ereh eht ot kcab dnim ruoy gnippans ,ylpeed serons si-eh-reveohW   … hhhO
;etihw-no-etihw yb dednilb
.nibac eht ni redliw sworg ytrap eht sa
,tfirdwons a ni gnittis er'uoY   .dloC
.tfoS .lufecaeP .dehsuh
.oot eulb ylbaborp era srae dna elzzum ruoY
.tnet a ni er'uoY
?yeht t'ndid ,dekan kcub anuas eht fo tuo nar uoy nehw trops ni dereej dna dehgual yehT
,keehc ruoy sbur yltneg eH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.das si eulB .eulB
,trihs kcehc gib a s'erehT
.gnitrofmoC .oot esae tA
?—lleh eht erehW ?savnaC
stcudorp lanoitaercer dna stirips ,eniw fo lluf — sdneirf ruoY   ?rebmemeR
.nuf rof niaga gnileef daed emas taht teg ot tsuj
... htmraw sa ti fo kniht ot nigeb uoy taht esnetni os sworg dloc eht elihw eht lla
.daeh ruoy nihtiw sthguoht eht tsuj ,eciov nwo ruoy raeh t'nod uoy sa
.mra eht ta kool retteb a teg ot gab gnipeels eht fo pot eht tfil ylluferac uoY
,seye ruoy esolc uoy
.enod htrae no krow sih redisnoc dna
;gnivol dna eltneg erom eb dluohs eh taht ylluferac nialpxe ot ,mih ediug ot yrt uoY
?railucep ton taht sI ... tub ,digirf s’tI
?niaga eman sih saw tahW
.resolc dna resolc semoc der gnihtemoS    .ezoD
,yllacitamard nepo seye ruoy
,elbatrofmocnu tub ,mraw s'tI
,uoy gnildarc smra ,uoy dniheb yltfos gnirons s'eH .eb tsum uoY
.emahs ot tlep thgil ylbaresim ruoy gnittup — hsulp dna mraw
.wonk uoy ,llaf a erofeb seog edirP .resoP
— gnileef eht wonk uoY   sussateM yb
.nalp ot og syawla t'nseod tI
.rehtie ,loop eht ni flesruoy yalpsid ot tiaw dluoc reveN
?uoy t'nera ,ytrap yreve fo luos dna efil yrev eht er’uoY
."selaT droW 563" meht gnillac
.sussateM yb ”nI dewonS“
”nI dewonS“:yojne esaelP
fles ruoy ni elcici ynit a yrc uoY
.tem uoy enoyreve htiw deyot uoy ekil tsuj
.ylevitcnitsni ti od srevol emoS
.ytiniffA ruF no puorg "tpmorP yadsruhT" eht fo trap sa
,noitcif-orcim detimil-drow no neek ylralucitrap si eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
— od uoy tub ,yhw wonk t'nod uoy — dna kcab ruoy ot ylluferac uoy sllor eH
.redduhs regae na htiw xaler uoy dna
,uoy htiw gniyot s'tI
.ereht nwod mih leef nac uoY
rettilf uoY   .gnola lla ekawa gnieb ton uoy dah
?yeht od ,palf t'nod sgnidliuB ?uoy od rO
.thgin eht fo kcalb krad eht ot reverof tsol era dna
.evol ni nellaf evah thgim tsuj uoY
.ssenwolley dna cirbaf otni evloser ylwols sgnidnuorrus ehT .trela er'uoY
.tser ruoy morf uoy esuor ot ekorts dna
.ssengnihton otni hcaelb serutcip eht erofeb
?ecalp dirroh siht ni tlep trohs ylbanoihsaf a si esu tahW ?ruF
— s'tI .eromyna dloc ton s'tI    .ezoD
.ylevol s'eH .tsaeb wons A
,teef ruoy no seot eht ot gel hcae nwod neht
.ruf etihw fo aes a ni gnilkniwt seye kcalb laoc
.thguat eb ot evah emoS
?ecaf a tuohtiw od uoy lliw tahW
.kcab emoc ot uoy rof dehgual dna detuohs yehT
;ylleb ruoy revo dna tsehc ruoy ot kcab
.ylhguoroht eno hcae skcehc eh erehw
.enob gnikaerb a ekil tol a dednuos esab-liat ruoy morf kcarc eht ,llaf ruoy ekorb ecafrus drah eht hguohT
dnim ruoy hguorht ylfeirb tfird segami dwel sa duorp dna toh sworg gnieb ruoy fo trap llams eno ,tuo-etihw kaelb siht ni htaed ot gnizeerf si ydob ruoy hguoht nevE
?nibac eht rebmemer uoY
hcir si eciov sih tub ,dias eh tahw wonk yllaer t'nod uoY
sgnitirw sih daer nac uoY
dna mlac dna thgil s’tI .gnihton s'ti
smaerD .wonk uoy ,llew — esuaceb meht fo esnes ekam ot yrt t'nod uoY .smaerd egnartS   .smaerD   .thgif a tuohtiw yawa uoy sekat peels sa sedaf ssenthgirb ehT
ylffurg uoy ot skaeps eH
.gniht lufituaeb a s'tI
.wons sa etihW .teewS
.ytrap hcraes a rof tsartnoc hcum oot edivorp t’now uoy
,daeherof ruoy revo mra ruoy gnivom
.sregnif ruoy ta yllud erats uoY
.ylraelc kniht ot drah s'tI
dniw eht otni tuo wolb taht stnemgarf yci noillim a otni rettahs ecaf ruoy sekam ti gniyrt tsuJ
.eci fo edam tsohg dilos a ekil ,etihw s'eH