”,dnuow tohsnug a ffo gniklaw saw I“
.won gnitarg ssel enot sih ,sdnopser dnuohyerg eht
.ordnasselA noD ,uoy t’nevah ,ythguan neeb ev’uoY
.doof em thguorb ohw eno eht saw eh ,eromrehtruF
.peelsa llits ylekil er’yeht tub
.ereh erehwyna ti ekil srood rehto on era erehT
”,nareiK ,oot ,ssenisub ytsan siht fo derit m’I ,salA“
.gnihton ekil sllems moor txen ehT
”.won thgir eniaR eneguE ton ma I
.toidi gnikcuf a era uoy ,eniaR eneguE“
.em wollof doolb fo sliart on erus gnikam dna em dniheb rood eht gnikcol ,edistuo ylwols pmil I .ti denrae ev’I
.ffats gnissap morf serats gnol tsdima
”.noituac detacovda I“
?sgniht ym era erehw dnA
,sretaw naitamlaD ni sdoog rieht dna
.mih rebmemer I sa lufetsatsid dna tnagorrA
.roolf eht no ylleb sih no gup daed eht evael ew
,em dniheb rood eht esolc I nehW
,taoc sih snottubnu
,yad yreve netaeb saw eh ,ytivitpac sih nI
”.elbon ynwarcs emos ekil dekool uoY ?ti raeb uoy nac woH
”.roolf eht no erew uoy tuB“ .don I
,eneguE  ”.ylnialp kaepS“
.noegnud a ton ylraelc s’tI
.mih ta kool tneced a teg I dna ,teef sih ot steg eH
.yllanosrep ,sloohcs rof hcum ton m’I
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,ffutS yttopS yb
.won tnedifnoc erom ,edis htron eht ot revo ,rodirroc eht gnola dap I
,toof a htiw nepo rood eht hsup dna ,efink ym ward I ,ylluferaC
.eciov eneres erom ,repeed a htiw syas eh ”,nareiK“
.snottub sih fo tser eht dna spsalc rehtael wef a seodnu
,eveels sih htiw ecaf sih ffo doolb eht sepiw
,depacse tsuj I eno eht sa niahc a fo hcum sa si tI
,eman yb ton nwonk m’I“
sevals lles dna yub ot dediced I
.wap tfel ym no gnixif seye sih
.sseldnuos tuo emoc yeht
.sgnignoleb ym dnif t’now I esac ni tsuj
,tuo kool dna ,wodniw a ot esolc pu teg I
,wap tfel ym fo kcab eht htiw elzzum sih ssorca mih pals dna
”?neht ,renoos emoc uoy t’ndid yhW“
.wonk t’nod I ,seiceps hcihW
,deripsni nainalletsaC
.seraw citoxe yojne snaitamlaD
.noitcivnoc ssel elttil a htiw dnopser I
,kcab sih snethgiarts dnuohyerg ehT
.segnahc tnecca siH
.sgnitaeb eht ni trap ekat ot tnaw neve t’ndid dna ,gnihton did eH
,sriatsnwod eno eht sa emas eht hcum
.wap ym morf ettorrag ym gnidniwnu
,eciov sih snetfos eh nehT
.dnuora sregnif fo elpuoc a kooh ot em rof hguone ediw
,taoc tnereffid a
,telecarb eht nod I neht dna
.yrtnap s’noD eht ni ylleb ym llif ot erus ekam I ,evael I erofeB
”?erawa uoy erew ,em lleT
.ylthgit ettorag eht gnihctulc ,moor eno fo rood eht kcarc I
,sklis dna eeffoc dna ,saet dna secips rieht evol yehT
.htiw nigeb ot ,ot deil gnieb ekil t’nod I esuaceb ,ereh seman laer s’enoyna ksa ot reven denrael ev’I
,rallec siht ni dnuos ylno eht wollof I ,rodirroc krad eht nwod gniddaP
.rednuop-evlewt a pots dluoc ti ekil skool eno siht tub
.sehsub dna seert derucinam fo lluf nedrag a ssorca
,sessik eltneg s’tiK fo em gnidnimer
”.ruoh eht nihtiw ydaer meht tcepxe I ,selbats s’noD eht ni sesroh emos reednammoc ll’eW“ .sneffits eciov sih dna
,dray tnorf eht ot tuo daeh dna ,sevilo dna attecnap emos pu rehtag I os
,ordnasselA noD rof gnikool neeb ev’eW .thgirlA
.nwo ruoy no lla llec ruoy fo tuo er’uoy dnA
doohnoitan fo esnes detalfni dna edirp dna yenom fo evol suoedih taht evah yehT
gnol os rof no ti tpek ev’I tuB“
.rood nedoow ydruts eht saw ti rof gniog dah llec ym gniht ylno ehT
.ngised ni labirt kool hcihw snopaew dna sloot wef A
.gnihtemos nekorb ev’I kniht I .esuoh erusaelp a t’nsaw llec taht ,uoy llet em teL“
.tnemom a rof sregnif sih ta serats eH
”.daed erew uoy thguoht I .daeh ym no eb d’tahT
.eciohc on evah I taht saw nosaer niam lautca ehT .oot tahT .gurhs I
”.ezigolopa I ,desuac I gnireffus eht roF
.retsam teppup a ekil swaj sih gnivom yllufecrof
,emit emos etiuq rof siht ekil revo dekrow neeb ton ev’I
.sgniw tnereffid owt ot pu gnidael yawriats a htiw
.renosirp eno peek ylno yeht ro ,yad wols a s’ti rehtie oS
,ydnarb htgnerts yvan fo elttob a dnif I ,naelc ruf ym eparcs I elihW
,syawllah eht nwod dna pu gnihsur era sdiam dna stnavreS
,ksa I ”?saw I kniht uoy did kcuf eht erehw ,lleW“
dluoW“ .roolf eht no gnippird ,tsif tfel ym drawot sdon dnuohyerg eht ”,ydaerla owt ro eno deussi evah ot mees uoY“
”?neht deripsnart ev’dluow tahW
”!dnuoh ,stnemmoc ykrans eht htiw
...yeht ,emoceb I elpoep ehT
,nwod gnillaf era sresuort ym esuaceb oot ,tleb sih ekat I
.yas ot desaelp m’I ,tleb egareva ruoy ton s’tI
.stcafetra sseltnuoc sniatnoc moor eht ,skoob fo daetsnI
.eyd ruf eht rednu delaever si ruf kcalb erom dna
.lamina rehgih a fo lluks a ylsuoivbo yreV
”.yrassecen siht fo lla sekam hcihw sdratsab eht fo eno rehtona fo dlrow eht dir ot dalg tsuj m’I“
,tuo ehtaerb ylwols I
”?thgir ,cigol eht ees uoY
,dab eht shgiewtuo dlrow eht ni doog eht taht em sdnimer dna
.hguone gnol rof desivrepusnu evael srednim sih revetahw htiw rereknit eerf erac dna
elbanoitcejbo ni devomer netfo era selpmaxe tsom dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.ylekilnu toN .erus ,doolB
.bir nekorb ym htiw klaw nac I raf woh wonk t’nod I esuaceb ,hcram s’yad a naht ssel yllufepoH
.oot ,taht tuoba eugra aitamlaD ni srehposolihp eht esruoc fO
”?kniht uoy t’nod ,si gnihtyna fi ,esneffo gnignah a s’tahT
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
,gup eht dnif dna ,ti nepo ylluferac I
.ecnahc gnithgif a fo erom evah htob d’ew ,em no snopaew rieht dedaolnu yeht fi taht desilaer I
.dnuorg elddim on s’ereht ,eripme etah ro evol a s’tI
.oot ,yhw sseug nac I“ .yas I
,smialcxe eneguE ”,tsirhC“
.nareiK ,tsurt lautum ruo ot s’ereh tuB“
.em morf koot yeht gnihtyreve sniatnoc
,def neeb evah yllamron d’I nehw retfa sruoh emos llec ym ot rood eht snepo eH
.ydaer tsomla si epacse ot nalp sih tuB
.luferac ton s’eh fi nam yna nwod gnirb lliw taht
.gnihtyna sa yhtlaeh ,sdnats eh
,setar xat wol s’nworc eht yojne ot detnaw I“
,yrrufoS no seirots sih daer nac uoY
,odiF dnif I hcihw dnoyeb ,yawhcra na s’ereht ,rodirroc eht fo dne eht tA  .tpeK .lleW
...uoy dnim ,renwo lanigiro eht s’taht
.tniop siht ta mih ro em s’tI .llew tuB
”?uoy taht sI ...tahW“
.tsrif moor taht retne ,draug ydob ym ,uoy tel I emussa s’teL
.rof mih tluaf neve t’nac I hcihw noisiced lacitcat tnemom eht fo rups a ot sknaht tnedicca bmud a tsuj s’ti ,ti ot nwod semoc lla ti nehw dnA
.dellik flesruoy tog tsomla uoY
”.srenosirp peek ot dettiftuo saw ti wenk reven I
.esnes doog fo rotacidni na sa htlaew esu ro
.gnidleiy ti dnif dna ,eldnah eht tset I
.enilwaj sih gnihctarcs ,syas dnuoh ehT
.moor eht edisni pils I sa em ediug ytisoiruc ym tel dna
.sedulcnoc dnuohyerg ehT ”,nareiK ,og uoy erehT“
,slarom ro cigol rieht htiw walf a no thgil dehs uoy fi ,dnim rieht egnahc yllautca nac uoy ,revewoH
.uoy rof eno dah I taht dneterp tsuj os
,efink sih gnikat tuoba etatiseh I
.niks murd a ekil emarf rieht revo dehcterts ruf niht htiw
.namelbon a yb del ton ylniatrec efil a fo gnillet skram dna sracs tog s’eh ,revo lla dnA
.snoitanalpxe mlac s’dnuohyerg eht
.taht sa elpmis sa ton s’ti ...tuB
,kcen ym dnuora niks erab eht elkcit ti gnittel ,ecalkcen ym no tup I
.niap ni em ees ot sekil eH
,shgis dnuohyerg eht ”,hguone eurT“
,egaugnal tnereffid a gnikaeps m’I fi sa
.edih sih evas ot gnihtyna tuoba tsuj yas ot stnaw ordnasselA noD taht llet nac I
,swap sih no doolb ym evah ot tnaw t’nseod eh dna
”?hguorht og ot evah uoy did ohW“
.em dniheb meht esolc dna srood eht hguorht pils ylluferac I
,taoc ym fo meh eht otni efink ym pils dna
,tuo teg I woh ,ma I erehw tuo erugif ot evah I
.syas dnuohyerg eht
,niaga daeh sih sekahs eh nehT
”krow ytrid eht od attog s’ydobemoS“
,taoc sih ni eloh gnikoms a gniees rebmemer yltcnitsid I
seitivitca lagelli erom ro eno ni gnilaed ylbaborp s’eh snaem evila em tpek regnarts siht taht tcaf ehT
.siht rof deraperp t’nsaw I
.noitarepo siht fo niarb eht saw eneguE
.aes fo smret ni hcum ton tub ,noziroh eht no sniatnuom era erehT
”,em toohs yeht nehw
dnuohyerG siht ...naem I ...eneguE
.ekil eht nees reven ev’I“ .mih llet I ”,ti
.sselesnes ylraen netaeb saw I sa em revo doots ohw
”.dewo m’I eveileb I .yrtnap eht dnA“
,ti ot nwod semoc lla ti nehw ,revewoH
.cimedaca si tnemugra eht fo tser eht dna
dnA“ .yltnalahcnon srewsna dnuohyerg eht
,kcab gnir ym ekil ylraed d’I tuB
.ecnahc a doots reven tsidas eht lecraM rooP
”.ograc lagelli ...gnidart
.mih llet I ”,desseug I“
?klat ot eno I t’nera ,lleW .syaw
.rehtet a no gnignah ecneitap ym ,mih ta lley I
,rood eht kcarc I nehW
.teiuq os si ecalp eht yhw snialpxe tahT
,kcen sih dnuora smra ym kooh dna
.elbats eht fo sllems ohw taog emos yb edistuo dna sriatspu deggard gnieb ,lecraM dna odiF ees I ,tae I elihW
.rae doog eno ym gniyalps ,yas I ”,lleW“
”?ytrap eucser eht s’erehW ?uoy erew erehw ,skeew owt rof llec a ni em kcuts yehT“
,rodirroc elbanimretni rehtona ot em sekat tI
,em erutpac ot deen eht tlef eh yhw ,saw god siht ohw denialpxe ev’dluoc eH
,snainalletsaC eht htiw terces ni gnilaed neeb sah ordnasselA noD“
.no gniog s’tahw tuo krow ot evah I tub
.skeew owt rof denosirpmi laiciffo tnemnrevog a tpek eh dnA“
.ti dnif ot ekil yllaer ,yllaer d’I ,trohs nI
.ydob eht edih t’nac I os ,siht tuoba og ot yaw yssem a si ettorag eht ,yletanutrofnU
,daeh sih revo eriw latem niht eht teg ot eganam I tuB
.ytpme smees dnoyeb moor ehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.hguoht ,sehcaet doG rieht revetahw morf yawa raf oot devom evah aitamlaD kniht ohw wef a s’erehT
,krad si llec eht esuaceB
.gnihtyna naht erom ,demahsa sdnuos eH
,spaos dna slio fo egnar s’ordnasselA etal eht htiw ruf ym fo tuo llems tihs eht gnitteg ,krow ot og I elihW
.syas dnuohyerg eht ”,gnidnats er’uoy ,teY“
.yad yreve selbat rieht no tlas tup nac ohw esoht ot ylno lufesu era slaroM
,sredrob naitamlaD nihtiw erehwemos llits m’I erugif ot mees yeht dna seye ym no yler ot evah ll’I ,flesym naht erom hcum llems t’nac I ecniS
”.siht ekil tnaem yeht esilaer t’ndid I
,renroc a dnuora emoc I
.tcepxe t’ndid I gnihtemos s’ereht ,woN .ekoms nug dnA
,gnihserfer dna ,gniveiler s’tI
.esuoh eht fo syawllah eht hguorht gnir seciov eht raeh I
.stnalp depporc yltcefrep dna ssarg ot sdrayeniv dna seert egnaro ,sesor dliw referp ereh selboN
.os em elttesnu t’nseod aitamlaD ot kcab gnidir fo stcepsorp eht ,elihw a retfa dna
,erofeb deppals ylreporp neeb reven s’eh ekil skooL
,niaga deb eht no flesmih staes eh sa ,syas eneguE
.meht desirprus eh fi ecnahc retteb a doots ew deveileb eneguE
,evol dna thgil eht ot ,efil ni sgniht doog eht ot derehtet em speek ti tub
.lanosrep oot ton s’taht epoh I“
.yas I ”,t’nsaw yllaer tI“
.em no dlot enoemos dna
.enim saw gninosaer eht ,s’eneguE saw dohtem ehT
,selballys wef a tuo shguoc eH
.xof a rof etteliot ruoy htiw tneiciffe erew uoy em dlot yehT“
.hcum sa detcepxe I
,mih tih I erehw tops eht ot wap a stup eH
.tuo syap yllanif kcul ym ,thginoT   2 fo
.teef ym pu kcip ot evah I fi esirprus yb em hctac t’now dna
.emit gnideef txen ym erofeb llec ym no kcehc lliw ydobon ,ykcul m’I fI
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
”?fo desucca eh si tahW“
”.erus ekam ot tsuj tuB
,enog erew uoy dna stnaliassa ruo ,ekowa I nehW“
.doog gnikool ton era sgniht dlot m’I tub
.thgis no ezingocer I hcihw fo enon
,sselthgiew tsomla si ti taht thguorw ylenif os s’tI
,rab latem ,llams a s’ereht hcihw fo dne rehto eht ta
.srae ym ot gnitarg ,syas eciov niht a
.yltneg ti gnissik
,roolf dnoces eht ta secnahc ym ekat I
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.yllarebil fo knird I hcihw
”.em htiw tespu eb ot gniog si ereh nareiK ,won dnA
truh t’nseod ti yas t’now I“
.sdnopser eh ”,erusiel ruoy tA“
,swodniw llat s’moor eht fo eno fo gninepo eht raeh I
”.daed saw I ekil dekool ti esoppus I“
.thgin s’tI .krad s’tI
.meht htiw tnemeerga ni flesym dnif I
”?ereh enod ew erA .dnuoh ,sknahT“
,erom rehtegot sregnif sih sbur dnuohyerg ehT
ereh tuB .tuo dekconk tog I erofeb thgir ,traeh sih revo thgir
.niaga ti esolc I sa eldnah rood eht no doolb terref fo raems a evael I
dnuohyerg kcalb ...yerg ehT
hguonE“ .ecaf sih ssorca gnirettaps doolb terref
,moor eht fo elddim eht ni ,dnA
”?I ro uoY“ .wonk t’nod I ,ettorag eht ro doolb eht no rehtehW
,kcik txen sih petsedis I
,moordeb retsam eht gniredrob eciffo na ssorca emoc I ,lewot a rof dnuora gnihcraeS
.syas eh ”,tnuh ot elpoep erom on era erehT“
.slarom detats rieht ot erehda dna tcepser yeht dna
.hserf sllems ekoms eht tub ,ffo og nopaew yna draeh t’nevah I
.ksa I ”?deipuccoerp woH“
,derutpac neeb d’I tahw rof dna
.liated suougibmanu ni gnidart eht gnibircsed
.htiw nigeb ot tsixe ot evah t’ndid boj siht hsiw I esuaceb ,dnim od I
,eriw latem nit a gniliart
.enoyna detcetorp evah t’ndluow I dna em ni eloh a htiw eno eht neeb evah d’I ,tsrif moor taht deretne I dah esuaceB
”.mih ot yas ot gnihtemos evah thgim uoy derugiF“
.t’nera yeht ebyam ,eurt era sruomur eht ebyaM
.mih fo lortnoc emos niater I tuB
.daD regdaB yldduC
”...pu dekcik yeht tsud eht ...yletanutrofnU“
.ylbaredisnoc segnahc enot sih dna
.regnif xedni ym sa kciht sa eb ot kool ,sdoG eht yb ,hcihw ssariuc a ffo swohs dna
.rehtie hcnets esproc oN
,slwoj sih yb mih sbarg dna
.noitamrofni eht lla dah ohw eno eht saw eh ,rehtar rO
,ralloc suoedih taht fo dir tog I retfa ,sraey ruof tsal eht roF
.elbatrofmoc ro naelc ton s’tI
.kcurtsbmud ,ksa I ”?ereht s’ti gnittegroF“
.slaedi s’noitan siht erahs ton seod ohw enoemos ot sgnoleb
,lworg I ”.pu tuhs ,eneguE“ “-
.taorht ym ni gniworg ecnayonna gnileef
,efink on ,nretnal on
.no emoc ,gnimoc ti evah t’ndid eh yas t’nac uoy ,lleW .sselefil
evol ot modeerf eht ,tsenoh eb s’tel ,llew ,dna msilarebil ,modeerf eht taht wonk I tuB
.yawrood eht fo raelc gnipeek
,trihsrednu sih no ffo swap ym no doolb eht depiw ev’I dna ,enod s’ti nehW
”,uoy s’ti wonk I ,xof ,no emoC“
,tsehc ym sa daorb sa hcae era sredluohs siH
.deb eht no gnittis
tsom eht raf yb dna ,detcepser tsom ,tsegral eht emoceb evah yeht ,siht fo esuaceB
.selbaulav ro erawrevlis fo lluf smra
,yrenif sih lla fo deppirts
”,pu wohs yllanif ot uoy fo dooG“
,deggag dna dnuob s’eH
”?htrof gnimoc sdrawot evah enoyna dluow noitanilcni tahw neht
,stuohs desufnoc ,smaercS
.daeh sih edisni evloser ot smees gnihtemos
.erahs I dna eh taht esle revetahw dna
.derevocsid ton m’I taht yrassecen si ti
,tleb eht morf esool semoc ti dna
.dnuohyerg eht ta regnif a gnillevel
.niahc ym fo egde eht ta gniniarts
.elims suoiciv a dna ,sevolg kciht
,em gnillewot fo boj eht od lliw hcihw ,epac kcalb yM
.selur ruo wollof ot evah uoy snaem
,moor eht ssorc ot mih sekat ti emit eht nI
”.oot ,meht deloof evah tsum uoY“
.llew sa yhport gnitnuh lanoisacco eht dna ,sllaw eht dnuora dettod era stiartroP
.ecalkcen revlis thgil a deirrac ev’I
.rood egral a s’ereht ,hcihw fo egde eht ta
.snosirp tsom htiw esac eht ton yllausu si hcihw
.slluks wef a etiuq nees ev’I dnA
.eid ot evresed t’nseod odiF  .woN
,deed eht od ot hguone neeb evah thgim enola rehtael ehT
,daeh detlit htiw revo em skool eh nehW
.lluks devreserp yltcefrep a
,dneirf ym ,aitamlaD ni gnivil dna ,aitamlaD ni xat gniyaP“
,erifnug ot suoivrepmi t’nera sessariuc ralugeR
.skeew owt tsal eht nwod thgif ot ni elttes tneserper yeht tahw dna seirenif eseht fo yromem eht sa ,sredluohs ym morf stfil thgiew A .feileR
.ecno ta thgir em tih sllems gnitcilfnoc fo egnar a
”.xof ,flesruoy tiuS“
,srae ym setarg eciov sih ni tnemesuma dlim ehT ”.uoy ta kooL“
.sniahc ym kcolnu ot gniryek sih gnibbarg erofeb taoctsiaw s’lecraM no swap ym epiw dna renosirp roop eht fo niks eht dehs I
.llot rieht ekat ot gnitrats era seirujni eht dna
,tuo dnuof gnieb fo ksir eht ekat ot tnaw t’nod I tub
,rood nepo eht fo thgil eht no seiler thgis s’lecraM dna
.nees reve sah dlrow eht eripme detsurtsim
.esuoh sih rednu ,llec eno ylno htiw tiebla ,noegnud a peek seod eh ,naem I
t’nseod ohw xof eno eht teg ot kcul ym tsuJ
”.deipuccoerp esiwrehto saw I tuB
”?uoy ti saw rO“ .mih ksa I
.dehctaw eb llits d’eh ,semirc sih fo tsael eht saw taht fI
.dettif yltcefrep ,tcaf ni ,saw taoc dezisrevo na saw denigami dah I tahW
.tleb wen a em sewo eh ,sediseB
.enim sa kcalb sa si taoc sih ,htaenrednu dna
.ereh rodirroc rehtona tey ni wodniw a hguorht yks kcalb eht ni nwad fo secart ees nac I esuaceb ,gniw htuos eht eb ot nrecsid I tahw ot pu bmilc dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,reggad nelots ym fo edalb eht htiw tsehc eht fo kcol eht kcarc I
.esion hcum oot tel eh dluohs
.worran dna peets ,yawriats enots a pu dna
,elkcub suoucipsnocni ylgnimees ym ta pir I
.taht tnaw t’ndid I
.esuoh s’namelbon a ylraelc s’tI
,ydnarb eht fo tser eht htiw ecalperif eht otni og sresuort dna trihs dlo ehT
.ereh eciohc elyts lausunu na si hcihw
.sehtolc ym ro ,sloot rehto ro ,drows ym ro ,epac ym tuoba hcum erac t’nod I
,mih dekilsid I sa hcum ,ti timda ll’I
.evil ot yaw yhtrow a si ,emit a ta redart evals eno
.no swap rieht teg nac yeht gnihtyna ot mialc yal ot slaedi dna slarom ,snaem eht evah yehT
.boj tnatropmi tsom siht mrofrep ot dnim dna ydob eht evah I sa gnol os
.teprac enif eht gnilios ,srettaps ni tuo semoc tI
.esromer fo dnik yna leef t’nod I tuB
,ti ot ytilauq llah ecnartne na fo gnihtemos sah ni flesym dnif I moor ehT
,krow lacitilop dwerhs ot sknaht ,tey raw ta ton er’eW
.elbaitasni era ,wap rehto eht no ,snainalletsaC   .meht tuoba elbarimda tsom dnif I sgniht eht fo eno si hcihw
.tuo lla era sllaw ybraen eht no dettod spmal ehT
.telecarb dna ecalkcen ym dna
.seciuls on ,setarg on ,srab oN
,nepo ti egdun I ,ylluferaC
”.lla rof dlrow retteb a ni eveileb ew esuaceb ti od ew tuB“
.noisnam yrev siht ot nwod uoy kcart ot dah I dna
.worg t’now ruf erehw racs gnol a tsuj si niks fo pirts taht
.neeb ev’dluoc I sa evitarepooc sa ton m’I snaem taht ,netfo dna
wonk I .llec eht otni em htiw emoc eh dah
.ruf pmad ym revo epard I hcihw
.ffo skcor sih teg ot lecraM rof hguone ton ylraelc si no skool odiF elihw em gnikciK
,ffats nezod a flah tsael ta tnarraw ot hguone gib s’tI
,lufemahs yrev deredisnoc si denoitseuq gnihtemos fo pihsrenwo rieht gnivaH
,duht llud a htiW
”?he ,emit siht lla retfa em derebmemer uoy desirpruS“
”?ecalp siht ni gnieb uoy fO“
.shgiht ym naht rekciht era smra sih
.gniredrum ym od I nehw dekan dnuora turts ll’I taht slarom ot daed os ton m’I dna
,dehsinup eb thgim sdneirf rieht ro yeht wenk tnamrofni na fI“
.daeh ym hctarcs I
”.mih htiw secnatniauqca edam ev’I“ ”.guP
.tnecs gnorts nwo ym rednu ,stnapucco sti fo yltniaf gnillems ,moor tseug tsedom a dnif I ,edis rehto eht nO
”.od ot gninialpxe emos tog ev’uoY“
?ereh uoy era yhW .nialpxE“
.tsenoh t’nsaw I tuB
.ton ma I tub ,daed neeb ev’dluoc I
.seitluciffid gnihtaerb ,dal trohS
.elbon deracs eht fo tnorf ni nwod gnihcnuh dna deb eht morf pu gnitteg
.nedrag s’eno speek eno woh tuoba sgnileef gnorts yrev sah doG rieht ,yltnerappA
,esle gnihtyna od ot em wolla t’now snoitcivnoc yM
.renwo sti fo ecart on tub
,ffutsyttopS yb
”?loof a ekil detca ohw eniaR eneguE ti saW“ ”.noitidnoc
,seigolopa yhtgnel rof eno ton m’I“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ordnasselA etal eht morf deworrob ev’I sresuort fo riap a pu gnidloh
”.xof ,em no sknird owt ti llaC“
.ma I revenehw ,derutpac yllausu m’I yhw
.spetstoof deirruh yb decalper ,nwod seid noitommoc eht ,yllautnevE
...hgU“  .ti htiw tuons sih srevoc dna nikpan htolc a tuo sllup eneguE ”?ereh I ma yhW
.eugaelloc ym ta ti level I ,ycneidepxe dna erusaem doog rof dna ,efink eht gnihctulc llits m’I
.mih morf yawa gnicaf nwod gniyal dna roolf eht no dnuora gnillor
.ylpmis rettum I ”,sdraug owT“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.aitamlaD ni emit ym gnirud gniht rehtona denrael ev’I
...ym tuoba ecarG sih llet
,smra dna teef ym ot gninruter si htgnertS
,dehsilbatse llew dna elbaeganam tsael ta ,gnidecer ton
.tcepsus I ,noos rehtar cimedaca eb ll’tahT
.seod yletinifed ,tsegral eht
,tekcaj sih pu snottub dna ,no kcab etalptsaerb sih sllup eH
,tsitra etnatellid
.elzzum sih ffo elims eht kcams ot tnaw tsuj I litnu
,pu gud s’eh srettel emos em swohs dnuohyerG eht nehw demrifnoc era snoicipsus yM
.ma yllaer I ohw ot kcab em sgnirb doolb fo llems ehT
.thgirla ,sgniht eseht fo yna tegrof t’nod I taht yas tsuj s’tel
,renaelc ylbaredisnoc sllems llec ym edistuo rodirroc ehT
.tsirw tfel ym dnuora depparw ettorag ym gnipeek
.ereh gnitser ecnelis rettu na s’erehT
,kcen ym gnilkcit ezeerb remmus tfos a ekil
”,moorhtab eht fo esu ekam ll’I nehT“
,wenis dna elcsum fo sgnihsal htiw rehtegot gnurts era sdnuohyerg tsoM
”kroW ytriD eht oD attoG s’ydobemoS“
.elbatnuocca dleh eb ton lliw yehT
.ytic eht morf raf tub
.taht ekil t’nseod eH
,stoob yvaeh fo tes a tsuJ .gnihton on
.rehtie ,siht ni tluaf tuohtiw t’nera yehT
.syad dna syad rof no dewets ev’I taht ,elib pu dekrow hcum os tog ev’I
.ruf tfos sih ,sreksihw sih
,dnuorg eht ot nwod sknis eh
,kcen sih dnuora depparw ydaerla sah ettorag ym
.gnihtyna sa mlac ,syas eciov eht
,em sees eh sa srepmihw eH
,eciov detcirtser-gnihtaerb s’gup eht fo noitaercer tcefrep raen a no stup dnuohyerg ehT ”?od uoy did tahW
.mih rof etal oot s’ti erofeb gniod m’I tahw ees t’nseod eh
,niarts eht htiw sehca ydob yM
?em no emalb eht yal yhw oS
.oot sgnignoleb ruoy elotS
.rehtegot meht sbur dna sregnif ydoolb sih spid eh ,elbat edisdeb a no guj a nI
.erofeb ti draeh ev’I erehw rebmemer yleugav I dna ,staeper eciov eht
.nrael ot emoc ev’I ,rettal eht ecnahc ot nem tsom ni ton s’tI
.sdoog nelots gninwo ot tcejbo ylgnorts yeht tuB
.ereh noitcennoc fo dnik emos otno m’I erus m’I taht hguone egeil ym elttesnu seod sredrob ruo nihtiw esuac s’ainalletsaC ot citehtapmys selbon hcir gnivah dnA
,retaw eht segdums ruf sih fo yerg ehT
.mih stiawa tahw rof deraperpnu yrev dna
”krow ytrid eht od attog s’ydobemoS“yojne esaelP
”,thgir er’uoy esoppus I“
.eveileb ot elbissopmi tsomla dnif I hcihw
.ainalletsaC yb dehtaol yrev aitamlaD edam sah
gniraew erew uoy sseug neve t’ndluoc I“
,ti ekat od I tuB
,seulc wef a etiuq sniatnoc gniw htuos ehT
.kcab edir ruo no hcum sa em sllet dnuohyerg ehT
.sparts redluohs eht fo eno tfeh dna tuo hcaer I
.maerdyad emos morf pu ekaw ot smees
.sdrow ym revo elbmuts I ”-s’taht ...s’tahT“
,rodirroc eht fo dne eht ta moor tsal eht tuB
.ffo semoc leets eht ,rettalc a htiW
?neht dna won niap elttil a tuohtiw erusaelp si tahw esuaceb ,eciffo fo gnir ym no pils I ,yllaniF
”.siht tuoba og ot yaw doog a ton s’tI .lanosrep ti ekam ton rehtar d’I“
.gnirons enoemos fo dnuos eht
.noitnem ot erac I naht erom efil ym devas s’tI .ssel ro
.gniht fo tros taht otni er’uoy fi ,nodotsaM dna rettiwT no mih wollof dna
.segnahc msirennam siH
,retirw tsiybboh a
.gnirons eht fo ecruos eht
.kcen ym ta hctarcs I
.ytisoiruc lanoisseforp fo ria na htiw sksa dnuohyerg eht
,ecno em kcik mih tel I
t’nod esaelP“ .daeh sih swob
.nwod nrut rae doog ym leef I
.tnaw I reveohw emoceb nac I
.ylkciuq ,yas I ”,taht tuobA“ “-
,nwod tuhs ot eno hcihw wonk ot stnaw eh dna
.god a fo tnecs eht llems I ,tsrif tA
.ruf pmad ym yrd dna em revo hsaw nus eht leef I
.htiw sredart dna sniatpac tsenoh drawer yeht hcihw
.top rebmahc a esu ot woh wonk tsael ta dnik ruoy fo tsom
.tsehc llams a dnif I hcihw ni
,derevocsid tey ton m’I ecniS
”.daeh ym tih evah tsum I dna riahc a revo delbmuts I“
,gnikam noisiced cigetarts rieht ediug htlaew tel netfo ll’yehT
.sserttam eht no seohs sih htiw draobdaeh eht tsniaga kcab gninael
.llec nosirp ynit a ni tnemtaert elbirroh erudne ot dah dna ,hsubma na retfa
.diarfa m’I ,erudecorp fo rettam a ylpmis s’ti ,ereht morf dna
,si htaed fo dnik siht revetahw revo thgif doog a referp I hguoht esuaceb
.ti tuoba das yllautca saw I ton ro rehtehw gninoitnem morf niarfer I
.epacse rieht ekam ro ,stohs rieht pu enil ro
”.ereht ni tup flesruoy tog ohw eno eht erew uoY
,dekcohs yleniuneg gnikool
,riaffa rehtael niht a s’tI
.edisni ria hserf gnittel
...ssel si siht sa ,wap yb meht gnilgnarts naht yaw siht llik rehtar d’I tuB
.secalp gnulf raf morf kcab thguorb neeb evah taht sgnihT
”.ereht s’ti gnittegrof ot enorp m’I taht
.daeh sih gnikahs dna gniyrc ot gnirepmihw morf enog sah gup ehT
2 traP ,ffutsyttopS yb
.sresuort ym morf tleb ym pir I
,rood taht hguorht uoy toohs ot ecnahc eht evah dluow hsubma ni yal reveohw tnaem kcol a gnikcip ylwolS“
.moor eht edisni morf elbisiv si em fo trap on taht gnirusne ,emarfrood eht ot txen llaw eht guh I
.tesolc a ot revo neht ,em ta pu skool dnuohyerg ehT  ”?mih dnuof ev’uoY
,eb ot ecalp a evah I taht em sdnimer tahT
”,uoy tcetorp ot boj ym saw ti ,tnavelerri s’tahT“
,tleb nelots eht ot drows ym parts I ,teg ll’I sa yrd sa m’I retfA
hguoht ,era sniap dna sehca eht dna
.taoc sih epacse ot gniniarts selcsum kciht ,esuohtuo kcirb a ekil tliub s’eH .t’nsi
.reraelc elttil a semoceb ti neht dna
.der ni deniats yawa emoc sregnif sih dna
denosirpmi saw nareiK ,emit tsaL
.krow ytrid eht od attog s’enoemos tuB
.ylesorom syas eh ”,ffo ti ekat reven I“
.gnihtyna od erad meht fo enon tuB
,mih ot pu klaw I
”-tnemom elgnis a detsaw uoy fI
,doog taht ot gnidda dna
.repsihw I ”?eniaR .rM“
,slluks erom dnif dna ,edisni kool I
.ti htiw yawa teg nac eh skniht eh snaem hcihw
.ksa I ”?no gniog s’tahW ...tahW“
.swap ym ffo doolb eht gnikahs ,mih llet I
.eldnub gnikool railimaf a dnif dna
.ecnedifnoc s’draggarb a htiw raef sih sksam ohw ,drawoc a si eniaR eneguE“
.ecivres ruo ni rotartlifni tseb eht sa ylpmis tub
,yltsenoh ,naem I“ “-I ,eniaR .rM“
,doolb htiw llif sgnul sih dna ni sgid eriw latem eht sa tub
.oga gnol ,kcen ym dnuora ralloc evals taht tup yeht erofeb saw I xof tneconni eht ekil ,did I taht yas dluoc I hsiw I ”?dnim uoy
,yrarbil a ekil skool tahw ssap dna
”.won ti ot desu nworg ev’I
”,xof ,ytrap eucser eht ma I“
,ksa I ”?secnetnes htaed owt eussi nac eno esoppus t’nod I“
.nworc eht fo tnega na no wap a yal nac yeht skniht reveohw llik ot woh dna
.reilrae syawllah eseht hguorht despiart I ecnis evila emoc evah ot smees esuoh ehT
.eciton won ylno I taht mih tuoba gnihtemos s’erehT  ...dekooL
.railimaf erom ti sekam taht ,haeY
eroM“ ”.sdnuop evif-ytnewt revo hgiew tsum gniht taht ,sdoG eht yB“
.daD regdaB yldduC
?yas t’nod uoY“ .srewsna dnuohyerg eht ”,ym ,hO“
.hateehc a fo niuqennam nedoow a ot dehcatta stnemanro dlog emoS
,devomer meht gnivah ot tcejbo yllausu
”,eno tluciffid a s’taht ,lleW“
.sretrauq gnipeels ot detacided smees gniw htron ehT
.taht naht ti ot erom ylraelc s’ereht tuB
.evitisnes dna elppus ylgnisirprus si niks eht ,tey dnA
,gnol os rof ereht ralloc evals a deirrac ev’I
.won dnuohyerG eht ylno s’eh ,em ot oS
.mih tem evah thgim uoy
.detsetnoc ylhgih fi ,ssenisub efas a si esoht ni gnidart os
,rallec eht fo tuo yaw ym dnif ylkciuq I
,sniap dna sehca ym lla rof srednow seod hcamots ytpme ym otni lohocla fo egrus yreif ehT
,nelots ylraelc steknirt elbanoitcejbo sti htiw ,moor siht dnA
.naelc sevlesmeht gnipeek ta dab yllauqe era noitan siht ni roop dna hcir esuaceb ,llems nwo rieht pu gnirevoc rof ton tub ,seY .oot emufreP
.eceip redaorb a morf edam ,eciwt dedlof
?ordnasselA noD ...siht s’erehW ...oS“
...renwo rieht taht si yaw a hcus ni detneserp slluks tsom ot nommoC
.tnavelerri si mih no demrofni ohw yeht saw ti ton ro rehtehW
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.lortnoc ym fo edistuo semitemos ,nwo rieht no sevil dael
.ezeerb naeco eht sdrawot edir ew sa ,mih llet I
,dniheb fles laer ym evael I
.haeY ”.knits uoy ,doG“