.slevon lacissalc elpuoc a dna skoobtxet enitsirp ruof gnidnif ot emac yllautneve tI
.ecneinevnoc rof demmirt neeb dah enim
stibihxe dna sllaw eht gnitagivan yM
,tnemnorivne sselefil ,dloc eht otni tuo gnideepS
.sllah sti nihtiw tnemegduj evag regnol on ohw
,’sitnaltA
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.lla meht dnif ot gniog erew ew dna
.htarw s’erutaN rehtoM hguorht detsal llits yeht fI
.ksam citcra ym no srosiv eht derevoc tsorf ytsan fo tsug neddus A
.rekram txen eht otno ,eniF
levon tubed sih dehsilbup dna ,noitcif raluger dna yrruf etirw ot sevol ohw ,sicoV sumoD yb
.eb ot desu snoitazilivic remrof s’ytinamuh tnaillirb tey
,are wen gnimocni eht tuoba pu delip ecnedive retfA
.ekops ,llevoC deman drow eht fo esnes yreve ni raguoc a ,rekrowoc ym
,nihc sih revo delruc taht hteet s’erutaerc siht ekilnU
.deeps ym fo suoituac
tsap eht fo namow ro nam a dewohs hcaE
.evivrus ot redro ni skoob eht denrub ev’thgim
.trAtnaiveD ro noertaP no
.emoc dah seiceps rieht raf woh eveileb ot tluciffid saw tI
,ereht tuo saw yrotsih eroM
:sredro ym derebmemer I ,revewoH
.yldas ,devivrus stcafitra lla toN
skoob gniyaced revo deppets I
”.kcab troper dna nocaeb eht wolloF
:2# tseretnI-fo-noitacoL
,ega morf detlom ro oga sraey dekcasnar neeb rehtie dah syalpsid rehto ehT
.dnuorg dekcarc eht no gniyl sgnitniap egral lareves derevocsid I
.flesym ot thguoht I ,lufecargsid woH
.htarw s’erutaN rehtoM fo sraey fo sderdnuh morf nwod derettab erew sllaw esohw yrarbil a fo spets tnorf eht
snoitazilivic tsap fo yrotsih eht evreserp ot stroffe erew ereht
lennut eht sdrawot deppets I ,elcihev eht gnikraP
dluoc stseretni fo snoitacol eerht detacidni
,ni-evac a deraef em fo traP
leef ot resolc deppets I
.roolf yci eht derettil yllaturb klawedis eht fo sknuhc dna skcirb elihw
gnidliub eht fo strap suoirav ni stiperif edamnam fo ecnedivE
si yrots s’yadot dna
retniw erup eht llems dluoc I dna ,ruf laicaf ym no looc tlef ria ehT
.deddon I ”,risseY“
,kciht sa semit eerht revo eb ot dah elibomwons ym rednu eci ekil-dnomaid ehT
.evac eci eht fo llaw eht tsniaga
.deliaf raeg ym nehw serutarepmet orezbus tabmoc ot edam neeb d’I
wons dilos fo reyal a rednU
.shtped s’reicalg eht otni gnignulp elihw denethgit enilpiz eht no pirg yM
,”yarG reteP fo serutnevdA ehT“
.toof no nrevac eht esrevart ot reetnulov a dedeen yeht dna ,sriaper dedeen senord noitarolpxe ylno ruo ,em rof ylikcuL
.sniur nezorf-flah ni dehsurc ytic ledom a ni tna na ekil tlef I
.tlah ydaets a ot dewols yllanif drawnwod yenruoj ym dna
tcejorP‘ .wef denimreted a rof evaS
.yawa htaerb ym koot enola thgis ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
ni scitobor htiw detamaglama gnieb ydob ym
,srallip dna leets detsiwt fo sessacrac won
sicoV sumoD yb
.dennalp ylsuoiverp naht snoitidepxe erom rof gniwolla
.erutats thgirpu ym dna erow I raeg retniw eht saw
,noiger siht ni nwod dewols dah sreicalg ehT
”…ereh uoy gnidnif erutcip t’ndiD“
saw sihT.ti wenk tsuj I
,ciahcra woh em ezama ot deunitnoc ti
deltsen muesum tneicna na ot del ,revewoh 3# tseretnI-fo-noitacoL gnidniF
erutaef tibihxe deffuts eht morf em detarapes tahw tub ,tsap s’ega fo
.seiruj dna srotucesorp ,sreywal ,segduj fo dioved esuohtruoc a
”?syug ,siht gniees lla uoy erA“
.niaga elttorht eht depsarg sregnif yM
,diorhtna ssalC htooterbaS a sa ngised citeneg ym ,revewoH
.sreparcsyks eht ees ot edistuo kcab detniuqs I
.noitnetta ym derutpac meti eno tub
,diov etihw eht ni erehwemos
.enoZ efaS lairotauqE eht gnitceffa senimaf dna sraw noitar eht hguorht
.od ot desu sreyolpme namuh ym ekil srotsecna ym fo eno ta gnirats ,saw I ereh woN
,su htaeneb demrof dah skcolb ytic lareves sa ediw sa tekcop ria na ,yllaitnessE
,nodnoL eb ot desu tahw ni yawa sretemolik owt etis noitavacxe eht dettops I
.enord rerolpxe na yb derevocsid saw evac laicalg derolpxenu nA
,revewoh retal setunim lareveS
”,gnortsmrA“ .niatirB taerG
,1# tseretnI-fo-noitacoL gnidnif litnu pam eht dewollof I
”,nisuoc ,ereht yeH“
.enigne s’elibomwons ym devver I
.knilmmoc ym raeh ot em dewolla ylerab sdniw gnilwoh eht ,elihwnaeM
.roirp syad lareves derrucco elcarim a tub
,enilef dehtoot-gnol niatrec a fo puekam citeneg eht dna sbmil ym
.eci eht naht regnol neve detsixe htaenrednu ytic eht elihw
,tsoptuO eht ot kcab thguorb eb ot degamad oot
.dleh I stcnitsni namuh yna morf t’nsaw taht tub
.noitarolpxe erehpsimeH nrehtroN degnahc yltnecer
.ffo ksam ym koot I os ,em fo retteb eht teg ytisoiruc
.smeti yna htiw kcab troper dna
.tniopkcehc eht ta devirra yllanif I ,emit emos retfA
.ni gnihtyreve gnikaos ylwols ,derumrum I ”…elbaveilebnU“
”dioV etihW eht ni erehwemoS“
.snoitidnoc tsehsrah eht devivrus diorhtna na fo seidob lacinahcemoib eht
?daetsni slevon ecnamor dab eht dehcrot evah yeht t’ndluoC
.ecnerefretni emos s’ereht hguoht ,gnortsmrA ,raelc dna duoL“
.eci eht hguorht devrac ylhserf
,taoc lamreht a fo sreyal ni eot ot daeh desserD
,tsur fo seirutnec morf dehsilomed ro gninael emos
.tsap eht evreserp ot stpmetta s’nam fo ytpme sevlehs eht
.t’ndah eno siht tub
”…sretem derdnuh-thgie nihtiw nocaeB“
”.sruoh 00:51 nihtiw tsoptuO eht ot nruter dna deecorP
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,sraey fo sdnasuoht rof dekcehcnu dna dematnu saw epacsdnal nezorf ehT
”dioV etihW eht ni erehwemoS“:yojne esaelP
.llehs enillatsyrc s’reicalg eht hguorht wolg ot deganam ylerab enihsnus tey
,seitic tsol eseht gnirolpxE
.woleb snoteleks sa denodnaba niamer
,ikahK yb
,evoba gniliec laicalg eht hcuot ylerab
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,sgnidliub eht enigami dluoc I
.aremac rosiv eht detsujda sregnif ym ,ylluferaC
.syawla ekil ,luferac eb ot uoy deen I“
.setis lacirotsih s’erehpsimeH nrehtroN eht eugolatac ot stroffe gnivivrus s’dniknam dnuora devlover
,seman fo lanigiro tsom eht ton hguoht
,smrotsrepus cificaP ro seinoloc narahaS eht gnirudne eb ti rehtehW
.desum I ,esuohtruoC iboriaN eht fo em sdnimeR
9# etiS hcraes
uoy rof daer ,sicoV sumoD yb ”dioV etihW eht ni erehwemoS“
.flesym ot dekoj I
,serips ekil dednecsa latem fo shtilonoM
.msirorret gnivlovni slairt eht suniM
.gof retniw eht otni gniraeppasid erofeb sevlesmeht esolc srood ragnah s’tsoptuo eht ees ot rorrim weivraer ym ni decnalg I
.redluob-xuaf a no regit htooterbas deffuts a doots
.thgilnus eht htiw dedaf ti litnu llafwons esnetni eht morf noisiv ym dedleihs I .efil ot derrup tI
htroN eht fo sdamon detacidni
.stnadnecsed s’redliub rieht yb nettogrof woN
.noitavacxe rof tcatni eb llits
,dnuorg nezorf eht otni deddebme
,kcapkcab ym ni skoob eht htiw ragnah s’tsoptuO eht otni kcab gnivird erofeB
sciler dna semarf erutcip ytpme gnidnif ot del ylno
,elttorht eht detsiwt dna meht depiw I ,deyonnA
dluoc thgil fo maeb yM
sdrocer cirotsih dna setilletas htob elihw