.tcepxe ot ohw fo gnifeirb a nevig t’nsaw I ekil ton s’tI
.yaw ym daerb fo daol a flah gniworht erofeb ,stnurg meht fo eno ”,xof ,gnineve dooG“
.tsael ta ,erutcip eht ni dedulcni ssob a s’ereht oS
hsiw I  .neeb reven ev’I ecalp emos m’I
.yksir ylirassecennu si gniod er’uoy tahw ,won uoy gnillet m’I tuB
,erom emos em taeb ot sevom lecraM
.srettam lauxes ni tnaived yrev dnA .sseldoG
.elbatrofmocnu woh rettam on ,citcat noitadimitni yna yb ffo tup ton ma I
.ytitnedi ym gniyfirev fo snaem a sa
,nem yvan nainalletsaC dlo yb thguob neeb evah dehcnual sah aitamlaD spihs edart tnecer eht fo wef a etiuQ
,sdnopser eh ”,smoorerots s’ecarG sih dediar I“
.krab I ”?uoy era ohW“
”?xof ,od nac uoy tseb eht taht sI“
,srood rieht tuhs evah sesuoheraw rebmit ehT
,seod god eht naht erom mih ot teg ekoj eht stel terref eht taht llet nac I
”?rewsna ruoy fo gninaem eht si tahW .xof ,si nori
.kcals ot gninetaerht waj ,pots I
.ylduol ,sksa eneguE
.rof gnikool m’I nam eht sa mih ezingocer I
,sllih eht sa dlO
.yllarutan ,eneguE si enoG
,sregua fo tes daorb a ekil skool taht gnihtemos tuo gnillup
?nwot emoh nwo sih ni dewollof
.naem I tahw wonk uoY“  ”?nori nA“  .naorg I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
.sseltiurf si egats siht ta gnihtyna gniyrt ,evom ot tpmetta neve t’nod I
”!deerb taht fo dneirf a evah I ?zsavuK“
.sdiletsum era srotpac ym taht llet nac I ,llems eht morF
.rettam t’nseod em sllet ti tahW“
.citsihcrana fo tniop eht ot gnikniht-eerF .larebiL
.lwocs a ni nwod snrut elzzum ediw s’god ehT
.nwod steiuq ti ,thgin ta tub
,sih ot ybur lacitnedi na
,drawrof hcnerw daeh ym leef I nehT
.em htiw gnivah ylraelc s’eh nuf eht morf yawa lecraM gnillup speek ohw eno eht s’eh esuaceb
”,odiF ,won teiuQ“
,delruf slias ,yab eht ni spihs ehT
,syas eh ”?won hguot os toN“
,em fo tuo noitamrofni taeb ot gniyrt elpoep fo aedi eht ekil t’nod osla I
.tsud eht morf yraet lla era seye ym tub
.spetstoof tnelis ylsseldeen htiw dniheb gniggoj flah ,ksa I
.enim ot kced tnereffid yletelpmoc a htiw deyalp er’yeht ,tcaf ni
,em naht rellat daeh elohw a ,dnuohyerg ehT
”?uoy llet tuons ruoy seod tahW“
.em yb denetaerht leef ot rehtie tcepxe t’nod I dna ,meht fo owt s’ereht tuB  ”?ssob ruoy s’ohW
,drawni sgniws rood ehT
.ti gnilaever rof elbisnopser gnieb ksir ot tnaw t’nod I
.gniddap fo tib a htiw osla tub ,elohw ylno ton ydob ym sreferp tiK
.tuoba evom ot ysae dna tneiliser s’ti dna ,llew em devres s’ti tuB
,rood eht ta secnalg
.nepo rood eht skcik ylpmis eh ,semoc rewsna on nehW
,wap tfel ym no yrrac I gnir eht mih wohs I ,hsiruolf ssel ylbaredisnoc htiW
.etad ot eno tnasaelpnu tsom eht dna ,yats htnom owt a saw tahT
.yllufniap seye detsujda-thgin ym sgnits dna ,snepo rood eht sa srekcilf thgil ehT
,reverof ni xof a netaeb t’nevah I .tib a mih krow em teL“
,ehcanap fo esnes elinevuj dna seohs evisnepxe ,mrofinu sih htiW
.lecraM sa nwonk terref eht morf tnemtaert gnitailimuh dna ,sehcnup ,hcamots eht ot skcik htiw snoob ym rof yap I
.dehcatta noitatuper a fo gnihtemos htiw semoc eniaR eneguE siht dlot saw I
.edistuo rentrap sih swollof yllautneve tub ,snaorg em
,azalp llams a ot teltuo eht raen
,niap elbaredisnocni ton mih desuac sah eot sih htiw daeh ym gnilian dna
enotskcalB nosirP fo amora ytaep ,yssom eht ekil llems t’nseod ti dnA
,pu dekcik si tsud fo duolc a ,nepo seilf rood eht sA
,ereht ni ”opac“ drow eht hctac I
.htap sih ni flesym ecalp dna ,mih fo daeha pu goj I ”.netsil ,eneguE“
.llec ym tixe yeht sa syek sih gnihsidnarb
.lagel saw ssenisub rieht fi sesimerp rieht ot tuo dellac eb t’ndluow I ,esruoc fO
.troffe hguone ni gnittup ton s’eh sleef eh ,ylraelC
.tohs gnol a yb noissim siht no warts trohs eht nward evah I taht erawa ,elbmurg I
”?uoy esaeler dluoc ecnarettu na tsuj nehw
.citamarD .lanoitomE
.ecarb daeh muirotanas a ot evol ytsur dna hguor edam ev’yeht retfa
.emarf s’namelbon ygdup ylthgils ,yriw a si emussa I tahw rof egral oot hcum si tekcaj sih dna
.ecnarusnI dna gnirekorB-gnippihS aznadaI dna onaiverT ekil gnihtemos yas dluohs ti ,yromem morF
”?su erofeb ereh neeb evah ohw elpoep eht fo
,seod ylniatrec lecraM sa ,esilaer ot gnitrats s’eh spahreP
,seippop fo sessenisub ehT
,ni yab eht meh hcihw retawkaerb detcurtsnoc eht no detacol
.meht ot si aitamlaD tahw ma I
.su dekcatta reveohw era enoG
.thgiew yna no tup t’nac I esuaceb tsuj s’taht tub
tahW“ ”.boj a od ot ereh m’I
,em eciton t’nseod dnuohyerg ehT
,tuo thgin dloc eht peek ot no tsev dna trihs kciht a tog s’eH
.snoitasrevnoc hguorht tuctrohs a sa ruovaf ym ni desu eb nac sihT
”?em htiw enod er’uoy retfa thgin yreve nwod uoy sdloh ohw eno eht ton fi ,neht ,uoy ot odiF si tahW
”?on a sa taht ekat ll’I“ “-
.sdnopser eh ”,ti od ton ot noitanilcni on evah I“
”.elttil a mriuqs eno siht ees annaw tsuj I
.stnirptoof eht gnisahc esacriats eht pu tnirps I
.gniyrt fo kcal rof ton tuB
.syad eseht efas oot eb reven nac enO
.rentrap sih ot gniddon
,liaj ni emit fo erahs riaf ym tneps ev’I ,denoitnem I sA
.detartsurf gnitteg s’eH .gnikrow s’tI
”.uoy wonk ylniatrec I tub
.nwod og t’now pihs ruoy taht sesimorp lles yeht
.tsud eht ni tnirpwap a gnivael ,retsinab eht dnuora gnilriws
.yltneuqerfni oot tae dna ,drah oot krow I esuaceB
llaw eht tsniaga gnileer em gnidnes ,worb ym stih toob siH
.gnitarg ro wodniw a neve toN
.noegnud retaerg a fo trap eb ot em ot tseggus t’nseod rallec siht ,tcaf nI
.stnirptoof eht ta neht
.snoissessop ym fo yna rof sehtolc ym dnuora elbmuf I elihw
.evila em peek ot dlot neeb s’eh taht
.elpoep ot gniklat ro sgniht gnidaer ot semoc ti nehw yllaicepse
neht dna ,ti otni slaoc tup uoY
”.stnirptoof tneceR
.daetsni yawa llor I
.tcaxe eb ot ,sterreF
”?gniht taht si tahw ,sdoG“
.tnecs fo eerf er’yeht tuB
?seod eh ekil nem ekil t’nod uoY“
”?won thgir dewollof uoy era dnA“ .daeh ym ekahs I
.xof ynwarcs ,sselpleh ,evissap siht no nemsdraug nworg owt peek ot deen on s’ereht taht
,erehwyreve tsuD
.gniht fo tros taht otni er’uoy fi
.gniraeh ot desu m’I naht tnecca rehguor a htiw tub
ydoolb a tahw wonk I“
”.xoF ,neht og s’teL“
.yllaer deen I lla s’taht ,yllausU
s’erehT .aitamlaD ni ereh ssenisub lagel t’nera hcihw sgniht eerht ylno er’erehT
,dnuora kool dna drows ym ward ,moor eht otni hsur I
,rood eht ecaf I ,llaw etisoppo eht sdrawot gnilbbarcS
.steerts enotselbboc s’ti sa ytic siht fo trap hcum sa si taht amora tneserp-reve na
ll’uoY“  .seye sih sllor god ehT
.enot evissimsid yrev a htiw taht ot sdnopser rehto eht tub
.ffo pael I erehw ,dne eht hcaer I litnu foor elit-enots eht nwod edils teef ym tel dna ,hcrep ym morf nwod pils I
”.eman laer ruoy ton sI“ “-eriuqse
,ta tpmetta ot gniog neve ton m’I hcihw ,gnitirw fo hcnub a si eno driht ehT
.retsamruobrah ehT
,evah ot thguoht doog a si seitlucaf ym lla evah
.tnecs a edih ot syaw ynam era erehT
,tcepsus I gnilbmag sih ot kcab teg tsuj rehtar dluow ,nretnal eht sdloh yllausu ohw ,eno rehto eht ,odiF
.skrep nwonk ressel wef a htiw semoc aitamlaD ni gniviL
.sraet dna niap fo xim a morf srulb noisiv ym dna ,niaga stun eht ni em skcik eH
,ynoloc nainalletsaC a ni evals a saw I
,selbon lla er’yehT
,htuos gniog pihs a fo girb eht ni tup dna derutpac yllautca saw I ,noisacco eno nO
dlog ni tes ybur der a htiw denroda
,emit sih htiw seod aitamlaD fo ekuD eht tahw tuoba eziroeht ot suolupop eht ni thgiled niatrec a s’ereht dna
.rof em gnimalb s’eh wonk I hcihw
.ainalletsaC htiw sisirc siht erofeb
,niahc trohs ym no nac I sa thgiarts sa dnats dna ,pu teg I
tsrif ehT .gnirettel detniap htiw srennab savnac dna
.petsrood ruoy no seugaelloc ym fo eno evah ll’uoy dna ,selur eseht kaerB
.senituor ’sdraug eht ni eloh yna pu derus sah raef taht erehw
,nwod rehtruf teef neetfif emos foor a no teef ym no dnal I
”?he ,hguot os ton skooL“
.era yeht reveohw ,su no pmuj eht tog yeht eveileb t’nac I
.dad regdab yldduc
.kcarc nac nam tseb eht neve esuaceb
”.esle enoemos detcepxe I
.tuo ti kcits I tuB
.evah yeht naht snosirp ni emit erom tneps ev’I taht llet nac I tuB
”.seohs ruoy ni erew I fi
;tsudwas dna elcaert
.rood eht sdrawot spets dna ,edisa em sevohs eneguE
,edisaes eht ta stekram hsif eht fo stnecs eht ti htiw seirrac ezeerb ehT
,syad dlo eht morf solletloC s’ekuD eht fo stnanmer eht fo eno neeb evah tsum eneguE
...os gnivoM“ .mih ksa I
aitamlaD fo ekuD eht
.yzeehw tahwemos eciov sih ,syas god eht
”,enod er’ew nehw knird a uoy yub ll’I
,ynam gnoma ,boj ym si tI
.klaw sreirrac rieht erehw gnitniop
.eussi na eb ot ton thguo yllaer ti erehw sgniht ni
.aineleH ot tsaoc naitamlaD eht nwod
.derednihnu llec ym fo trap yreve hcaer ot hguone yaweel em swolla llits ti esuaceb
.tey gnikniht fo yaw ym ot dnuora emoc etiuq t’nevah aitamlaD fo snaicitilop eht ,revewoH
.em sksa eh ”?dewollof uoy ereW“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,neht dna won yreve sehcni wef a mih evig I
.wonk t’nod I ,taht esimorp nac yeht woh etiuQ
”.zsavuk detaoc kcalb ,gnitsugsiD“
,ni semoc lecraM nehw ,yad enO
,esac eht yllausu s’ti esuaceb ,tcepsus ot gniog m’I
.diova ylerab I taht yaw ym kcik a sdnes eh
,noisserpxe suoveihcsim a otni stfihs eno yknal eht no ksam kcalb ehT
.ris ,yrros m’I ,yhW
.esruoc eht rof rap lla s’tI
.s’eneguE ton si eciov ehT
.tnasaelpnu dnif yam seninac taht
.kaeps snaitamlad evitan nehw pu peek ot elggurts I naht os erom neve ,ti dnatsrednu ot elggurts I
.revo elbuod dna ,naorg I
.wap devolg yvaeh a htiw elzzum ym ssorca em stih eH “-yhtlif uoY“
”krow ytrid eht od attog s’ydobemoS“
.yas I ”,terref ,won emoC“
,xim eht otni seiceps ym gnirb elpoep nehw tib a sgnits llits ti tuB
.os thguohT“ ”?tahW“
.eramidem eht fo strap repeed eht morf pu egderd semitemos yeht
.edalb eht fo htgnel eht snur taht noitatnemanro eht otni sdnelb hcihw
.egamad fo yaw eht ni hcum gniod ton tub
,tuo sruoh ruof ekil gnihtemos tnuoc I
”?pu gninaelc fo erusaelp eht ylnO ?ereh dnif eno nac erusiel tahW“
.tekcub on s’ereht dnA
.epac dna taoc ym dna
.eniaR eneguE .eniaR .rM“
,slworg eh ”,arsop et goB“
.em ot gnitseretninu
,sngis daehrevo ,seuqalp doow htiw desitrevda si elbanigami ssenisub yna ,sroolf dnuorg rieht morf dna
,ecnegilletni ot enorp netfo dna ,erus ,elbmin er’yehT .yhw wonk sdoG
”.riS .ecaf a llac uoy ekoj taht ni sesaerc eht tuo nethgiarts oT“ ,ezeehw I
.dleifrats nwod edispu na ekil gnirekcilf
,sruomur eseht epacse tonnac ew taht hguone elbazingocer era su fo wef riaf A
.tcirtsid elohw eht ees nac I
”.sleeh ym ta nemow gnilliw fo egaruotne na peek I ,og I reve
,gnol os gnibmilc neeb ev’I sesuoh-wor eht fo eno si ot sgnoleb llaw eht gnidliub ehT
,esle enoyna ro em ees t’nac eh nehw ,neht
.egdub t’ndid god ehT
.tsif sih gnihcnelc
”?taht od ot evah uoy oD“
.reffo ew setar xat elbaeerga dna krow evitarcul eht rof sruo ot eripme taht morf emoc evah ohw
,dnopser nac I erofeb dna ,selbmur eh ”?he ,yug hguoT“
.edart rieht no snoitcirtser on yal ohw
,sracs fo erahs riaf sti tog s’ti hguoht dnA
.ekas ’tsirhC rof ,eltsac eht rof krow I ,eb t’nac yeht esruoc fO
”,od I esoppus t’nod I“
”,em ksa ot naht retteb wonk dluohs uoY“
,slanesra s’ecarG siH
”.nori nA“ ”.evil uoy tel
,reknab a eb dluoc ohw eH
,won pu tuhs uoy fI“ “-ot uoy era ohW
.siht naht esrow nees ev’I .tey
.redrah era sehcnup dna skcik siH
.dnif t’ndid dneirf daed ruoy gnihtemos rof gnikool
,esacriats eht no stnirptoof fo stes wef a etiuq s’ereht taht eciton I ,neht tuB
”,teg uoy eno eht ma I“
,nodotsaM dna rettiwT no mih wollof dna
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
”.od nac I hcum os ylno s’ereht ,enoemos morf noitamrofni tnaw uoy fi oS .seno lanoitnevnoc eht naht erom hcum tog t’nevah I“ .ksa I
,flesym ,gib ylralucitrap ton m’I
.swap ym ta pal nac nretnal s’aznadaI dna onaiverT fo thgil eht erehw
,dnamed I ”?uoy era ohW“
,efiw tnetsixe-non ro evitcepsorp sih ,eugaelloc sih
.kcol rood eht fo kcalc gniyfsitas eht raeh I sa krep rae doog ym gnittel ,elbmum I
,s’aitamlaD ton dna egaugnal taht kaeps I yhw osla si hcihw
.meht dniheb thgil nretnal prahs eht tuo tolb serugif owt dna
.aedi on sah ohw enoemos fo eciov elbaekatsimnu eht ni ,syas eneguE
”.liat ym evah uoy tel ll’I dna
,niaga dna niaga ,em sehcnup eh sa slworg eh
.em teem thgim uoy
”?rof ti esu uoy od tahW“
”krow ytrid eht od attog s’ydobemoS“
,seno ypool eht tup yeht erehw draW satireV ekil-rewes eht ro
fo ekat nac I erom hcum woh erus ton m’I
,etatse-laer naitamlaD fo klub eht pu ekam sesuoh enots detniap ,elap eseht
.erusaem doog rof tpek yeht slamina draymraf eht dna
.krow sih ni flesmih sedirp ohw terref a si ,em ot smees ti ,lecraM
,eb dluoc I naht desiurb ssel em gnivael
.mih llet I ”,nareiK s’eman ehT“
.etagaporp meht tel ot tnedurp ti skniht sieR ekuD tub
,hO“  .suoesuan em sekam niap ehT
.yas I ”,eniw droffa nac I“
.ees ot gnihton s’ereht ,roolf dna foor ,llaw eht ni senots eht rof evas tub ,erom yas dluoc I
.eciffo fo laes a si rehto ehT
.lecraM .lla s’taht
,htlif ruoy ni gnillor dna srevotfel elats gnitae ,ynoga ni
.sksa eh ”?siht ekil
.desufnoc os saw I
.tik kcipkcol ym dah I dah ,kcolnu ot ysae eb dluow hcihw
.mih rewsna I ”,noitseuq dednim-elpmis a tahW“
,ksa si od ot deen uoy llA“
.nosirp fo dnik emos ni m’I fi sa
denruter uoy evaH“ .sdnopser eh
.ytsenohsid rieht fo sllet
”,mih ni tfel emos tog s’eh
,roolf tsrif eht fo kcab eht sdrawoT
.hsibbur ylbaborp dna ynit era srae sih dna ,ruf dna niks fo sdlof ni deirub tsomla si tuons siH
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.drows sih fo tlih eht htiw rood eht no deppar s’eh ,skcip kcol ym tuo llup dna flesym rehtag nac I erofeB
,ekoms doow htiw ria eht fo tser eht llif
,uoy tnes ohw sseug ylidaer nac I
”?krow ro erusiel rof ereh
.gnimmals rood yvaeh a dna gninrut segnih ytsur fo dnuos eht
.uoy tuoba swonk ohw dna
.stun ym otni thgiarts ,eno rehtona sdnes eH
,seye sih ,erutaef tnenimorp tsom siH
,waj reppu ym ni seninac decalper owt dna
”?rof kool uoy did tahW
.emit tsrif ym ton s’ti ,niagA
,sliated tnatropmi eht fo tsom htiw dehsinruf neeb sah eh ,puorg elttil ruo fo dael eht sA
.sgniht ynam os hcuot t’noD .rethgil petS
.rof gnikool si lecraM rewsna eht yltcaxe s’tI ”.ytliug sa
.yllaer ,ti tuoba tespu os ton m’I ,thguoht dnoces nO
.lwob llams a ni retaw emos dna daerb fo faol A
..I“ ”.eveileb I ,gnirekorb gnippihs dna ecnarusnI“
,em gnikcarc s’eh taht leef mih tel ot
”?dednim elpmis uoy erA“
,won ereh eb d’eh ro ,gniniart hcum dah evah t’nac eH
.god derb-erup a s’eh em sllet erutcurts laicaf pu dessem ylhguoroht ehT
”.su dnif ot elpoep rof drah ti gnikam ton er’uoY ?ylsuoivbo
,seerged lareves flesmih gniniartser ,eniaR .rM
era esehT .ffo em stup llems ehT
.denodnaba tub lla era ecnarusnI dna gnirekorB-gnippihS aznadaI dna onaiverT fo seciffo ehT
sa si hgual ekaf yM
,selbmurg draug rehto eht ”,no
”?rood taht dnoyeb enoemos era ereht esoppus uoy oD“
srednim sih revetahw htiw rereknit eerf erac dna
,ekaw I sa selttar daeh yM
.rehtegot tisiv syawla owt ehT
.spetstoof rieht gnidih fo elbapac eb dluow
.drager taht ni ereh snoitadommocca ym htiw yppah yrev ton
.seye ym nepo I sa
,ereh nwod efil ruoy dneps ot tnaw uoy oD“
,rehtom dna rehtaf sih
.foor eht fo egde eht sdrawot yaw ym ekam I ,yltfos ,nehT
”.yawa srotarepo decneirepxe ssel nethgirf ot esur a tub s’tI
”.ereh ni rof gnikool er’ew tahw fo secart
,leets dna rehtael deliob ni deruomra htob er’yeht tub
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.snoegnud eltsac eht ton
.tisybab ot decrof m’I sonilletloC dellac-os eseht
,srab dna snni fo sesion tnatsid eht era sdnuos ylno eht dna
.god tnagorra ydoolb ,bmuD
.erac t’nod I ,ylknarF .era sredro ruoy tahw wonk t’nod I
.tleb ym em tfel ev’yeht tuB
.rof gnikool m’I tahw rof ti ezingocer I taht sepahs dna sruoloc thgir eht sah ti tub
,noos yrev siht sesilaer eh ,yllufepoH
,snoegnud dna snosirp ot rotisiv raluger-imes a saw I erofeb dnA
.roolf eht no paeh a ni eil ylno nac I litnu
,ykculnu yrev er’uoy fI
.erutseg tnayobmalf a htiw edisa taoc sih spils eh erofeb steerts eht gninnacs ,elims a ni kcab ward spil siH
,xof kcalb suoiretsym eht m’I ,snezitic wollef ym oT
,revewoh ,noitan taht edistuo enoyreve oT
,sredluohs ym no nael ytilibisnopser hcum oot gnivah ekil t’nod I
.sedis rieht ot depparts sdrows epyt-suidalg trohs tog htob ev’yeht dna
1 traP ,ffutsyttopS yb
,rof gnikool erew uoy tahw em llet ll’uoY“
.god tnagorra ,daeD
moor eht fo ezis eht fo aedi na uoy evig dluohs hcihw ,gnol teef eerht tuoba s’tI
,mrif ym fo seciffo eht otni emoc ev’uoY“
,snirg terref ehT
dekcik ohw terref ehT ”.taht ekil eb ot gniog er’uoy fi emit txen eht kced ym gnirb t’now I
;gnihtyna evoba railimaf si sihT
.oot ,ti syojne eh smees ti dna
,foor delit yalc ,llat a fo pot eht morF
.stuhs rood taht sa meht ta gnikniw
.sdos tnagorra era gniteem fo erusaelpsid eht dah ev’I seno eht lla taht noitnem ot toN
.kcab ym no revo em gnikconk
.ylimaf layor eht fo sevitatneserper htiw tcatnoc esolc ni nees semitemos
,mraerif a fo noisolpxe duol dna ssih ,kcalc eht raeh I ,hguoc I sA
.niaga em skcik eH
,ti ta gnikool ,esu sti sseug nac I
”,esoprup dednetni rieht rof desu neeb reve ev’yeht esoppus t’nod I“
taht tekram hsif eht ta sgniht esoht fo eno fo dnim ni em tup
,llab gnitehcocir a dna ssalg fo gnihsarc eht neht
.ssim t’nseod kcik txen sih dna ,revewoh kcab em sknay niahc ehT
,hctorc ym rof thgiarts seog eh dna
.ereh enod era sgniht woh meht dnimer ot
”.rof ereh emac I tahw od trepxe eht tel dna
.llew sa srae rieht dehcaer evah xof kcalb suoregnad dna erar eht fo sruomur taht
,ecalp ysub yrev a yllausu si aitamlaD fo ruobrah ehT
.em ta slwocs eh nehT
,nosaer emos rof ,staps ym nekat ev’yehT
thgim I ,em llet uoy fI
.kcol eht no krow ot og dna ,mih dniheb pets I
.era euniter sih ni sretcarahc egnarts eht lla ohw dna
.stnega sih tsgnoma sdnuohyerg sreferp
.su dnuora lla tsud pu kcik hcihw spets tnedifnoc htiw ni sllorts eH
,sthgil mid erom wef A .owt dna owT
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,ffutsyttopS yb
.etiteppa ym niager I revenehw rof em peek ot daerb fo faol a htiw tub
.taht ekil lla ton er’ew tuB
,gniliar ynoclab a no nwod pat ylteiuq dna
.si taht ,seye thgin ym tog ev’uoy dedivorP
.nruter t’nseod god ehT
.drawoc emos ekil swodahs eht ni edih t’nod I“
.ereh rood a neve s’ereht taht esilaer ot stnemom wef a em sekat tI
,lanosrep yrev siht gnikat s’eH .seod lecraM tuB
.htgnerts sih rettalf emarfrood ysmilf dna segnih ytsur eht tcepsus I
”krow ytriD eht oD attoG s’ydobemoS“
.emas eht hcum era syad wef txen ehT
,sesoprup dna stnetni lla rof ,skool ti esuaceB
.eneguE rof nepo rood eht gnidloh erofeb
.ytud draug ot lahsram dleif a detomed enoemos ekil ailager sih lla ni gnikool
yad yreve dneps ot tnaw uoy oD“
.niarret eht fo trap ekil leef yeht
,mih sdrawot em fo secnereferp lauxes eht ot ecnerefer rehtona ro thgils a ,esruc a mih evig dna doolb tuo tips I ,em htiw enod s’eh skniht eh emit yrevE
,meht dniheb rood eht esolc yehT
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT.siht
.erom no mih gnigge trats I
,erbas yrlavac a fo ffo stnilg evoba nretnal nekorb eht fo thgil ehT
.shtap tes evom thgil fo stod llams ,ti tsgnoma gnivoM
”,xof ,noitseuq raelc ytterp a deksa I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ydob ym fo erac gnikat ton rof em sedihc syawla revol yM
”,ti esu dluoc uoy derugif eW“
.tisiv ot snoisacco eht dah ev’I snosirp rehto eht fo yna ro
”?thgirla ,htiw revo siht teg tsuj s’teL“
.taoc sih ni tsaerb elbuod eht hguorht eloh gnikoms a
.selbmurg draug tsrif eht
thgin ta aitamlaD   2 fo
,syas dnuohyerg eht ”,xoF“
,strad gniworht prahs fo yarra dna efink ,drows yM
,eunevA s’rekameldnaC dna onacileP aiV neewteB
,rehto eht naht renael si enO
emoC“  .syas em dekcatta ohw terref eht
.srehto ot nekopsnu semoc taht ecivres emas eht em edivorp ot elpoep retsep ot evah I
”.ti esu nemow rehsaw
.em morf nekat ev’yeht
,naitamlad ni eugolaid fo sehctans emos egnahcxe riap ehT
,tcaf ni ,ma I dna ,no peels ot ecin osla si gniddaP
.enituor emoserit a
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA   .tnemaciderp sih sepacse nareiK woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,oot ,ruf kcalb ym sevol eH
.tey tuo ti dedeew t’nsah ecarG siH dereggats tsuj m’I
.yllacitpyrc rewsna I
eb dluohs ereht ,revewoH“ .syas eneguE
,tey timil ruoy dnuof t’nevah uoY
erehW“
,yllacitamotua steerts eht dnuora skool eH
.sdrawpu gnidael esacriats a seifitnedi eneguE
.lecraM morf kcik tfiws a flesym gninrae
,detpecretni tog--setarip erew yeht—pihs tahT
,gnikniht lacihposolihp dna citsitra fo tnorferof eht ta yltnerruc si aitamlaD
tnecs rieht ksam ot tcelletni eht sah reveohW
,htaenrednu sessap dnuohyerg eulb ,referp yeht sa ro ,yerg a nehw ,oS
,slworg dneirf terref ym ”,xof ,eugnot ruoy dniM“
,smra ym fo hcaer eht dna ,sgel ym fo htgnerts eht dna
...lla fo rotartlifni tsetaerg ehT-“
.elfir a htiw rehtona ,exaelop a htiw enO
”,klat yeht epoh s’teL“ ”.recnivnoc A“
,roolf knalp ytsud eht si enoG
.wenk I elpoep ot snoitcennoc dah niatpac esohw
.pu nekow tsuj d’I fi sa noisserpxe derit a no gnittup
.evila mih peek ot snoitcurtsni htiw dehsinruf neeb ev’I elihw
.mih sselb ,siht htiw seerga ,tiK ,revol yM
.laudividni driht a yb deinapmocca era sterref eht ,yad eno ,nehT
.ti rof degnah eb ton dna nam rehtona evol nac I erehw fo wonk I yrtnuoc ylno eht s’ti dna
.moor taht otni dael stnirptooF
.hguone gnol rof desivrepusnu evael
.tuo mih gnipeek erad yllaer t’nod uoy tub tnemhsilbatse ruoy ni tnaw t’nod yllaer uoy mohw nosrep a ,yracs tib a m’I
.snoissim suoirav gnirud
.mih sa sselerac sa flah t’nerew stnirp rehto esoht tfel reveohW
.evila uoy peek ot era sredro yM“
”.tfig a eb ot tnaem saw tI“
.enoyna otni nur t’now ew taht tnedifnoc ,mih wollof I
,dootsrednu ev’I tahw morF
.bir a dekcarc evah skcik s’lecraM fo eno dna
.erofeb em netaeb reven s’eh ekil em staeb eH
.ereh ni ria sselefil ,elats eht morf gnigduj ,kniht yllaitini I tahw s’tahT
.erom elttil a denekcals hsael sih gnivah ni erusaelp taerg sekat ohw
,thgilhcrot si ees nac uoy lla ,ton fI
.yna sa evitnecni na doog sa si ,seveileb eh ,raeF
.ereh ni elbaulav gnihtyna dnif ton ll’ew taht em ot stseggus hcihw ,riaffa lerrab elgnis A
.rood s’eciffo ecnarusni eht revo gnignah nretnal tilnu ,elttil eht no dexif seye ,gnitiaw
.taht rof emit fo ytnelp eb lliw erehT ...lecraM“
,llafthgin retfa demrofrep si yrtsudni esohw srehto ro sexof-thgin ,srethgil pmal era esehT
uoy stniap noitseuq yrevE“
.llaw a no srood tes-esolc owt tops I
,rentrap sih ot syek eht sdnah eh dna
,dne eht yb llec taht fo tuo mih gard odiF tel syawla I tuB
,sseug nac I ,esuaceb flesmih sniartser eh tuB
,yrrufoS no seirots sih daer nac uoY
,ligis ylimaf a si sdrawot detcerid neeb ev’I sserdda eht ot gnignoleb ngis
.mih tsurt nac I os ,tsael ta edoc eht s’tahT
.lluks ym hguorht sniahc leets gniggard s’enoemos ekil sleeF
.eeffoc fo dnof ylralucitrap m’I taht toN
.krow ot og yeht revenehw nwod tup nac yeht hcihw snretnal deen ohw
.stoob dehsilop ,taen sih fo elos eht tsniaga gnirettaps pil tilps ym morf doolb
,tuons ym rof mia ot tnaem eh taht llet nac I
.em ot resolc gnippets elihw
.gnihctef s’ti kniht rehtar I
,noitamrofni lufesu erom edivorp ot gniog ton er’uoy fI“ “-t’noD“
.mih llet I ”,xof a m’I“
,teef sih ta tips I
.enot ydaets ylgniyonna na ni ,syas eh ”,em nethgilnE“
,od t’ndluoc I neve yaw a ni ereh tuo sdnats eh
.dloheb ot thgis a si
.debrutrepnu syas eh ”,xof ,hsinif em teL“
.em htiw llec siht gnirahs
.elttil a struh eno taht ,timda ll’I
,tius gnorts ym t’nera sgniht esohT
.mih spots god eht tub
,lecraM ot sdon ylno god ehT
”?ti gniod uoy era yhw nehT“
.ti no gninael m’I
”?sloot eht lla thguorb uoY“
”.hguot ti sah dnik ruoy wonk I“
.ti tuoba kniht ot ton referp I tub
?secaf dnasuoht a htiw eno ehT-“
.noitcivnoc ssel dna ssel htiw yb dnats nretnal sih htiw ,odiF elihw
.ecnetnes lanimret eht meht htiw yrrac taht sgniht eerht ylno era ereht tub ,taht naht ecnaun erom tol a yllautca
.moor eht fo elddim eht ni roolf eht otni nevird
,roolf eht no delwarps eneguE dnif I
.shgual terref eht elihw htaerb rof elggurts I
.detarepsaxe ,rettuts I ”?tahW -I
.od I sa roolf enots eht no swalc ym lla gnineprahs ,dnoces yb dnoces
.rood eht ta tneserp ton erew hcihw
.eramideM eht morf ezeerb elbaeciton ylerab a ni yltneg kcor
”?uoy wollof enoyna diD .dewollof t’nsaw I esruoc fo ,oN“ .daeh ym no ruf eht gninethgiarts ,rettum I ”,dnuoh ,uoy esruC“ ”.egrahc ni m’I .xof ,pil oN“ .em sffuc eH ”.saw I erehw wonk neve t’ndid uoY“
.sraey rof ni tas neeb t’nevah hcihw sksed dna sriahc dna
”.thgirb yrev ton m’I wonk uoY“
.sdrawot gnidaeh erew ew rood emas yrev eht sdrawot dael hcihw
.tcepxe nac I sa gniteerg a lamrof sa
,noitamrofni taht tcetorp ot si boj yM
.eciov sih ni kciht noitcafsitas-fles ,syas eh ”?dewollof I mA“
.deciton ev’dluow enoemoS
,sdleif eht fo remraf ro ,rennat a ro
.noitatuper a evah sexof wonk I ,woN
.syad fo elpuoc rehtona rof nur siht tel I
.boj eht od thgim rabworc a ekil skool ,sediseb detsur s’tI
,etar driht nainalletsaC emos yb deerf saw I dna
,xof ,em wonk t’now uoY“
,hcrep ym no niamer I tub
,doolb gnissip m’I esuaceb
.meht nihtiw secnereffid eht ezingocer dna sdeerb eseht rof tuo eye na peek ot denrael ev’I tuB
”.krow ytrid eht od ot tog s’enoemoS“
.tnasaelpnu eb ot gniog s’eno siht ,kcuF
.srekcins ecaf yknow eht htiw god ehT .em ta gnittips
.edisni dewolla ton ma I erehw dna ,esihposolihp ot og hcir eht erehw ,sajčotovak ro ,sesuoh eeffoc denepo ylwen esoht dna
.wonk yeht tahw wonk ot deen I tub
,nrut a sekam eneguE ,pot pU
,ni gnimoc hguoc ytsan a tog ev’I
”?rof krow uoy od ohW“
,srood tnorf s’ynapmoc ecnarusni eht fo tnorf ni flesmih snoitisop
”.thginot doof tuohtiw pu mih kcoL
.doolb ward ot gnihcti tsuj s’eh dna
.yllautneve ,kaerb
,dedworc yltcaxe t’nera woleb steerts ehT
,reyolpme ym ,ecarG siH
.eneguE ediseb nwod hcuot dna ,gniliar ynoclab eht fo og tel I  .yletilop ti tup ot
.rettalc t’now ti taht os htaehs drows ym gnippirg
.redrah elttil a deirt dah eh ylno fi
,kcen ym dnuora ralloc a ot dehcatta niahc trohs a fo knay eht yb dedrawer ma dna ,pu teg I
.tnecs xof ym sehctac eh llet nac I tub
yojne esaelP   .daD regdaB yldduC
,edis eno ot dnats ot uoy etivni I neht
hguoht ,ecivres yratilim laer morf mets sladem sih taht stseggus yliratnemom hcihw kcik taht ni ecrof a s’erehT
,tsud eht ni stnirptoof eht ta tniop I ”.kool dnA
.seciffo ytsud eht ni regnol on m’I llet nac I tub ,snips moor ehT
.seye dna eson ym otni duolc taht fo tsom sediug ecnedivorp dna
.elpoep niatrec yletinifed si lecraM dna ,sevren s’elpoep niatrec no steg tahT
,redluohs tfel ym rednu thgir stcennoc kcik txen ehT
.kcalb seog dlrow eht dna
?slliks ym noitseuq ot uoy era ohW ?dewollof I saW
,rellevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sevals yb detaerc gnihtyna dna ,sevals
.yvaeh sleef ydob elohw yM
.gnikil ym rof duol oot rehtar ,syas eneguE ”,ytirahc ergaem ruoy peeK“
.bmuht desiar a fo mrof eht ni ngis raelc lla lareneg a sevig eh
sworruf sseltnuoc ni dees sih gniwos
I taht tcaf ehT .daeh eht ni degamad yltnenamrep pu ekow ohw ,tuo dekconk evah I elpoep ,tuo dekconk elpoep nees ev’I .emit tsrif ym ton s’tI .tneipas siht eb ot ykcul m’I ,ecneirepxe morf dna ,tuo dekconk neeb ev’I
.htaerb rof gnilggurts m’I nehw
.thginot rof ylno si emag eht tuB
,won dna ereh thgir lufpleh yrev ton s’tI
.noitnetta ot krej I dna ,skaerc dna stfihs rood eht ,nehT
”?era sboj rieht kniht uoy od tahW“ ksa I
,llems gnorts rehtar a evah dnik ym fo emos wonk I
,esle erehwon ekil dnuoba sruomur ,aitamlaD nI
.eciov a nehT .pmuht a neht dna
.uoy rof yldab og ll’ti esle rO“ .dnamed I ”!em lleT“
,taht efiw ruoy ksa d’I“
,gnitirw htiw dellif segap derettacs
”,emuserp I ,elpoep gnicnivnoC“
.snoitadnuof mrif no tliub syawla t’nera sllaw latnem dna lanoitome rieht taht ecneirepxe ym s’ti hguoht
,retirw tsiybboh a ,ffutsyttopS yb
.yab laicifitra s’aitamlaD ni deroom sredart gib eht draobno secips dna stiurf erar fo sgnat eltbus eht dna
,sreyolpme dlo rieht morf gnola stibah dab rieht thguorb evah eseht fo emos tuB
”.gnisol er’uoy hcihw ,eunitnoc ot alukširB fo emag a evah ew“
.tekcub a dah I ,ereht neve tuB
”,flesruoy nialpxE“
,foor eht morf nwod pils I
.secaps thgit dna syawllah worran ni gnithgif rof tcefreP
.sehcrot htiw sdrauG
.rettum I ”,hguot uoy wohs ll’I“
,ytpme si moor eht taht ees ot erus gnikam ,tsrif edisni pils I
.ffocs a htiw syas eneguE ”,hcum oot emuserp uoY“
.esoppus I ,meht fo tol a ni neeb ev’uoy nehw teg uoy gnileef a s’tI
sngis eseht fo erutan suoivbo ehT
.srepap dna sksed eht
.ecnedifnoc gniyonna htiw srewsna eh
,eno laer ym sa gnicnivnoc
.niahc dna telecarb revlis ym dna ,gnir ym nekat ev’yehT
,eniaR eneguE taerg ehT“
.yllufrednow gnikrow s’tI
,tsitra etnatellid
,kcoldap elpmis a htiw denetsaf si kcen ym dnuora ralloc ehT .sruetamA
.ksa I ”?gnol rof desolc neeb seciffo eseht evaH“  ?tsuD
.ksat ym ni deliaf I dnA