.sag fo tuo tsomla saw rac sih dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
:mih dnuora ni desolc uoyab eht fo sdnuos ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.os kniht t'nod I ,oN"
.wap dereffo eht koohs dna
".daor eht ta s'ti tub ,edis eht ot ffo dellup I ,naem I .haeY"
.wolg teloiv gniregnil a dleh yks eht tub ,oga ruoh na revo tes dah nus eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,lluks sih tsniaga denettalf srae siH
.yltcerroc llacer I fi ,regrahc a uoy lles thgim noitats saG
si yrots s’yadot dna
,wonk'Y" "!diputs oS"
.won thgir ton ,lleW .mU"
"?ay od ,krad eht ni llew oot ees t'nod uoY .pup ,ereh revO"
....tsuj I dna etatsretnI eht ffo noitats sag eht ot sngis eht daersim evah tsum I dna tfel I erofeb pu leuf ot togrof I tub ,dnekeew eht rof snaelrO weN ot teg ot gniyrt tsuj m'I"
"?he ,tsrif dnuorg eht ffo pu uoy teg ew t'nod yhW
.tuo nettog dna rac eht deppots tsuj d'eh dna daor a nwod ffo derednaw dna dnuora denrut tog dna noitats sag a dnif t'ndluoc
.gnileviws srae sih
.did xelA naht reinnuf rehtar gniht elohw eht gnidnif eb ot demees eH
.pleh dluow ti hguoht sa ,ylmrif ti dekcams xelA dna
,irauR nosmirC yb ”sserpyC ehT nI erehwemoS“ saw sihT
.eraps ot owt ro nac a evah dluohs I dna ,ecalp ym ot kcab yaw eht wonk I ,lleW" .deddon yaR ".krad
?tuo ti kcehc og
thgil on htiw eert a tsniaga krad eht ni gnittis ,saw eh ereh won dnA
41 taeH ni seirots trohs sah ohw
tsuj dna esruc a kcab tib xelA
,hgis gnol a tuo tel xelA ".enif
tsuj eH -- tsuj eh dna nrut a dessim eh ,erehwemos ffo dellup yllanif d'eh emit eht yb dna rac eht gnileufer tuoba nettogrof tsuj dah eh esuaceb ,rac sih ni sag erom teg ot yaw emos dnif ot gniyrt ,thgil on
,ereh hguorht daor eno ylnO
,deid dna derettups thgilhsalf eht morf maeb ehT "!won toN
;yks eht tsniaga rallip rekrad a
.redluohs eht no mih deppalc
,pu hctac ot tiag sih dehcterts etoyoc ehT
,hguone llew dekrow syawla dah ti esuaceb ti gnicalper ot dnuora nettog reven d'eH
.og ot detnaw syawla d'eH
.flesmih sucof ot deirt eh sa yltfos detnap etoyoc ehT
.delkcuhc god ehT ".regaw
ton yhw ,thguoht d'eh ,snaelrO weN ot sruoh xiS
.saw ti thguoht eh erehw saw gnihtoN .lufssertS
!niaga toN !oN !on ,hhA"   irauR nosmirC yb
.srae sih neewteb wap a nar eH
.tsol m'I ,haey ,hgU"
;yltcerroc dellacer eh fi ,ytivitisnes lluf ot setunim ytnewt
.rehtie ,taht rof pots ot ecalp yna nees t'ndah eH
.yllufknaht ,on
,elbisiv ylerab saw tI
!ffo dnekeew a dah eh dnA
.dnuora yaw sih dnif ot gniyrt llits saw eH
.tsrif-daeh ti otni gnilbmut
.daeh sih morf elgna nwo sti ta tuo gnittuj hcae
,ylivaeh ti tsniaga gninael tsuj
.hguoht ,erofeb siht ekil revo mih dewercs reve t'ndah tI
.yawa gniniard noisnet eht gnileef
.sdnuos dnuorgkcab eht revo dereyal krad eht ni elbmur wol A
sdap retfos ,nwo s'xelA ta thguac dna desullac dna derehtaew saw tI
enihw a kcab tib eH .dewercS
.derebmemer eh eert tsal eht sdrawot deklaw dna
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.doow eht tsniaga daeh sih gnikconk erofeb ton tub
,irauR nosmirC ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
.lla retfa ,eurt eb tsuj thgim taht ekil mih ot demeeS
.tey ni delttes ton m'I
mih fo tnorf ni tuo sdnah sih dleh eH
esruoc fo esuaceb ,daed saw enohp sih dna
syawla dah rehtom siH
,ni saw eh etats tahw erus ton
uoyab eht fo elddim eht ni tsol saw eH
.ytrebiL a tsuj s'tI
.daeh sih koohs yaR ".gnisseug
.hguone noos rac ruoy dnif ll'ew erus m'I os
.daeh sih koohs eH
.taht htiw pleh ot gniog si eert eht no tuo sniarb ruoy gnitaeb kniht t'nod I
.krad eht ni ti fo kcart tsol I dna ,tfel hcum ton s'ereht tuB
.eert eht tsniaga daeh sih dekconk dna
.dum eht ni dnuora gnipmort rof seohs ecin lufwA
.yllaer ,doog saw tI
.noisiv sih morf gnidaf seert sserpyc til-ylthgirb fo
,ylwols gnitsujda erew seye siH ".xelA"
.evah emos naht esnes erom s'taht ,lleW"
”sserpyC ehT nI erehwemoS“
.eromyna saw rac eht erehw erus neve t'nsaw eh dna
.egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna 1 WALC dna
"?thgir ,gnol tsol neeb t'nia uoY
htworgrednu railimafnu eht ni gnilbmuts
,stoor eht fo eno revo deppirt dna
.regaw I ,dedeen uoy lla toN" .deffins yaR ".noos
egami retfa eht htiw mih tfel thgil eht fo htaed ehT
.ykcinif elttil a neeb syawla dah thgil eht -- thgim tI
,neht ,oot ,pam a htiw detros uoy teg ll'I ,pup ,lleW"
.pu flesmih dellup xelA dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,flesmih hctac ot deganam eH
.mih ot txen krad eht ni god fo tros dnuoh gib a tuo ekam tsuj dluoc eh dna
,oot ,taht fo erac ekat ot nettogrof d'eh
.evom a neeb dah tI ...neeb dah tI
"?pup ,daor eht no tuo rac ruoy evael uoY"
”sserpyC ehT nI erehwemoS“
.mih ot txen nwod dettauqs mrof krad a litnu gnihton was tub ,dnuora dekool eH ?yllaeR ?gnihguaL
,noos revocer dluow seye sih ;rac eht morf raf enog t'ndah eh
,meht neewteb yaw flah ebyam ,saw eh ereh dnA
dnah a mih dereffo god ehT
?neht ,ereh tuo yaw rednaw uoy d'yhw oS"
.krab hguor eht tsniaga daeh sih gnitser
.yawa dnah sih dellup eh nehw
.erom yna pu flesmih dloh ot evah t'ndid eh dalg
.enif eb lla ll'tI
"?tset-ih sdeen taht tros
.wap a tuo kcuts eH ".tsol
.dewercs tsuj saw eH
.hgiht sih ot thgit ni dekcut liat sih dna
,uoy od ,ycnaf 'nihton evird t'nod uoY
.delttes uoy teg ll'ew dna ,neht ,em wollof lleW" .deddon god ehT ".ytrebiL
.odaroloC ni emoh kcab sniatnuom sih ekil gnihtoN .ysion os saw tI
.dah tsuj ti ekil ,tuo tuc ot dekil tsuj ti ,semitemos tuB
.tuo teg ot woh uoy wohs dna
.elzzum sih fo tuo dellol eugnot sih dna ,dennirg yaR
.pots tip a ebyam dnA .klaw a tsuJ
,eyA" ".deid tsuj thgil yM
.gnisseug atros m'I os ,esruoc fo ,daed si hcihw ,oot ,enohp ym dnA .rac eht ni kcab si hctaw yM
.dab taht tsuj erew sgniht ,oN - eh
notsuoH fo tsae erehwemos
.detcepxe eh naht erom pu teef sih kcip ot gnivah dna
,sgorf ,stekcirc
wap gib a neht ,elkcuhc rehtonA ".tey
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,tuo gniyrc esle tahw swonk doG dna
-- noitisop lamron rieht ot gninruter ,xaler srae sih tlef xelA
derugiF .thgil a tuohtiw gnineve eht fo emit siht enif tsuj gnola teg ereh klof tsoM .taht was I
.noitats sag tseraen eht ot selim evif s'tI
,seye sih denepo xelA ".taht
,gniht diputs eht tsniaga denael
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
".raeh I ,oot ,smoorhtab saH
:yojne esaelP
,hA" .nwo rieht fo dnim a evah ot demees yeht dias
.strap eseht morf emac sklof ruoy ekil kool t'ndid ,haeY"
.niaga eert eht tsniaga daeh sih dekconk dna dehgis eH "....tsuj
.boj a rof notsuoH ot devom d'eH
...s'tI .ereh nwod devom tsuj I"
.tsol neeb athgim uoy
.noos laer sag dedeen I
,knurt eht nwod dils dna dnuora denrut eH
:dab taht t'nerew sgnihT
.gniht diputs eht rof hguone diap erus d'eh dna
toof sih htiw eert eht dnuof eH
.niaga deirt neht ,desuap eH "...I ,lleW"
.tsrif deppots I ,oN" "?tuo nur uoY
.ybraen gnilppir retaw
deddon xelA ".yaR s'emaN"
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer