,nehctik eht dnif ot tnaem oilorB
oilorB "?ecnamrofrep ruoy gninnalp noonretfa lufsseccus a dah uoy tsurt I"
.hcraes ot serac eno fi ,derevocnu eb yam yrots repeed a tey dna
,noisrev etanretla eht dezingocer dah ehs wenk oilorB .dennirg dna
eman sih yb mih llac reh
.tuo dnuof eb dluow oilorB neht os fi dna
,ybbuc eht ni derewoc oilorB   2 fo
.ecarG ruoY ,niaga ecno em ronoh uoY"
.etisiuqxe saw taht"
.gnitiaw-ni-seidal s'ssehcuD eht fo eno
,yreneerg gnidnuorrus eht tub gnihton was
,gnituohs dna gnimaercs
ro ,decnuonna egap eht ,"os-dna-oS ydaL dna droL"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.tnemenifnoc ot eerht eseht reviled ,tnaegreS
.dehgis ssehcuD ehT "?won neppah lliw tahW"
.gnikaeps erofeb
”.tsaef remmusdiM eht erofeb rennid uoy sreffo eh
.bo reh fo deer eht gnitsujda flow a dna
meht ecudortni dluow egap a did yeht sa dna
.'semihC esuoH lliH'
.enotS ecneiduA eht drawot deklaw dna
ssehcuD eht ",I naht os erom toN" ".tsrif ti deganam uoy
.srebmahc ruoy ot uoy dael lliw I
kcalb-dna-der a ni desserd ,sredluohs depoots dna
.nwo s’ssehcuD eht sa detniop sa ylraen elzzum a htiw dnuoh nael a
,htaehs terces emos morf nward dah eh efink a ,dnah s'rodassabma eht ni gnihtemos ffo detnilg thgiL
.ti wonk ton did I fi deedni nodobort a rof esucxe roop a eb dluow I dnA" .dias oilorB ",drol ym
ediw werg seye s'retsam-dliug ehT
?ti fo rednow eht ni saw eh sa pu thguac
,gniht a fo ssol eht si tahW
,ria eht deffins eH
",gnos a fo tseuqer a ekam thgim I fi
spil sih ot etulf erevatiaC sih tup oilorB
,oilorB retsaM ma I
sgnirednaem sih denodnaba oilorB ,snoinapmoc sih dna retsam-dliug eht gnivaeL
.stseug eht demrahc oilorB ,dessergorp gnineve eht sA
,niaga dewob neht ,rood eht denepo egap ehT ".nihtiw
,neht dna tsaef eht rof doof fo syart gniyrrac retne stnavres dehctaw eH
,daeh sih tsniaga talf srae sih
.emit erom thguob pis rehtonA ".emit
.alotaK dlot ehs ",rehtona htiw
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup
.tuo dellac eh ",ni emoC"
laem tsal sih taht mih gnidnimer
.emit a rof deraeppasid uoY" .dias onraL riS
.eman sih kaeps reh raeh ot tnemeticxe htiw derevihs oilorB dna
.rood ylno eht saw siht ,llet dluoc eh sa raf sA
",lanigiro sih saw gnos txen eht
.nwo sih dna stnemevom reh htob gniganam drawetS eht htiw ton
,ynam swonk nodobort A" .dias eh
,eciov gnizeehw a ni deksa nam eht
.os ti ekam ot ytiliba ym ni gnihtyreve od lliw I dna" ,dias eh
detsisnoc nwog reH .worb reh no deretnec saw dnah s’oilorB fo mlap eht fo ezis eht erihppas a dna
detterf oilorB ,htab rennid-retfa sih fo yruxul eht ni gnilever fo daetsnI
.enod dah eh ecivressid eht terger ot emit on dah
htuoy eht ,wob a htiW
?gninraw etauqeda na otni egdelwonk siht yalrap ot elba eb eh dluoW ?ynam woH
.mih ot dias ssehcuD eht
deraeppa dehctapsid dah ehs egap emas ehT ".tnemhserfer
deltitne si dna
.snoitadommocca eht rof lufetarg ma I
."tesnuS eht ni gniteeM" ,gnos txen sih nageb oilorB
,stnemilpmoc sih sreffo onraL riS"
.thguoht eh ,ylnialp reh nraw tsum I ,taht retfA
,dnoyeb tsuj eb dluoc drawetS ehT .flesmih dekcehc tub
,drohc tsrif eht kcurts oilorB
.nalp ot tops dedulces a flesym dnuof I"
.ronet yzeehw sih htiw ni denioj yllanif dna
denethgiarts eH ".nac uoy fi
.yks thgin eht ssorca daerps etihw dna eulb fo srewolf ,evoba hgih tsrub stekcor tsrif eht
.decneirepxe dah eh cigam eht tpursid ot
.cinap dewener fo piy a delfits oilorB dna ,dias eh
.ecnamrofrep tnatropmi na hcus erofeb eniw knird tonnac I
.werg nalp sih ni ecnedifnoc sih dna
.emit ni ssehcuD eht nraw ot ,wohemos
",drol ym ,em ronoh uoY" .dewob oilorB
ot srotiart eht gnitrela tuohtiw
.srodirroc eht gnirednaw mih dnuof ohw egap emas eht saw tI
,regnol elihw a detiaw neht
.dias yllanif eh ",did I"
".emoc ot erom si erehT"
,snaem lla yB" .saw eh sa pu depporp neve ,doots eh erehw delbbow eH .eson s’oilorB dellif -- taem dna ydnarb eht
.deltsub dna detaelp yletarobale
,esirpretne nwo sih dekcerw eH"
,nworf a desserppus xof ehT
.eciffus dluow lliks sih lla decnivnoc ton saw eh dna
.gnas eh sa sdrohc eht demmurts ylwols eh dna ,cimhtyhr erom
,anrotnuP morf rodassabma ehT
.deddon oilorB ".gnas eh sgnos eht ot sevitanretla ni deirub eb thgim egassem neddih eht taht desimrus I
.rewoT ssaldniW eht lortnoc ot mialc yeht hguoht ,won srehto eht no gnivom era eW .yletaidemmi dessefnoc yeht ,detnorfnoc nehW
,koot ehs enot lufnruom eht eciton ot deliaf eh taht ylno
.rood eht fo tohsrae nihtiw ybbuc a ot deklaw eh sa seidal eht ot daeh sih denilcni oilorB
”.ylluferac meht draug dna ,meht etarapeS
.noitnetta lluf reh
,rodassabma eht dna drawetS eht desuor ylhguor sreidlos ehT
,gnos leetneg erom eht fo rennam eht ni ,niaga noitcudortni eht deyalp eh nehT
.mih youb ot deliaf reven ecneidua eht gnisaelp ,thginot ecaf yletamitlu thgim eh sregnad tahw rettam oN
.tsaef eht rof noitaraperp etelpmoc ot devirra stnavres eht litnu
,wodniw eht tuo dekool dna moor gnittis eht ni
",nodoborT retsaM ,selzzup suoived tcocnoc uoY" .ylnaw delims ssehcuD ehT ".ton dluow uoy taht detterf I" .ssehcuD eht ot dias oilorB "!egassem ym dootsrednu uoY"
,evirra ot nageb stseug ehT
.thguoht eh ?deliaf nalp ym saH
sreidlos owt yb deknalf
,railimaf elttil a tsael ta ecalpemos
.mih erofeb puorg eht deyevrus eh
.stseug fo retsulc a otni dna ybbuc eht morf tuo deppets eh
.soahc neddus eht ta gnikrab dna gniyarb
,thgindim ta gnimool regnad eht togrof reven eH
"?tnaem yeht tahw wonk uoy did woH
,taht dna yaw siht srae sih denrut eH
,redluohs s’oilorB no ylivaeh dnah eno denael eH
,ydaer si tius gnimrofrep ruoY"
detfil traeh s'oilorB .ffo dehsad
.denwo eh gniht elbaulav tsom eht saw tius gnimrofrep sih
,ybbuc eht morf elzzum sih ekop ,ylluferac
.doof sih no gnikohc ,hguoc ot nageb eh dna pu dellew cinap s’oilorB
.denruter dah tnaegres ehT ".stseretni
,drawrof deppets reidlos driht ehT
.drawrof dekcirp srae reh dna
,"elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT" fo nur gnidnecsed lanif eht deyalp eh sA # .thguoht eh
.gnas eh sa ylyrw thguoht eh ,yadot eniw fo etsat tsrif rieht ton si sihT
.noitamitse ym ni lareneg-revo saw I" .delkcuhc ehS ".ocrabzU
snacrabzU" .draehrevo d’eh rotiart eht htiw nam laineg siht tcennoc ot tluciffid ti dnuof oilorB dna
.modgniK dnalsI eht hguorht delias I ecnis ton
.dias eh ",ecalap eht hguorht yaw ym tsol I timda I"
,dnah thgir reh no derettilg gnir lraep-dna-erihppas ehT
,meht dekcol dah onraL riS
,alehwib sih morf edisA
,htuom robrah eht dedraug srewot ssertrof owT
,sffuc eht ta slessat revlis htiw sehceerb ,trihs tnasaep a
,detiaw eh sa regna htiw derraw rorreT
lavres yratilos
.htaerb dleh fo psag a ni dias oilorB ",seY" ".srebmahc
.oilorB llits ot dnah eno pu dleh ssehcuD ehT
,selbat eht derevoc knird dna doof ,derekcilf thgil-nretnaL
,ssertsim reh ot kcab neht
,allerT ssehcuD eht ot detacided si tI"
,dessap dah yeht nehw
,latnemurtsni eht fo drohc lanif eht dedualppa ecneidua s’oilorB
,redluohs s'oilorB ot esolc ,tuo dnah eno dleh eH ".etisiuqxe
.noitartsurf sih gnithgif
,stils yrgna seye sih
.noitisnart tuohtiw niaga kcab neht ,hgih yb dewollof seton wol
,tius gnimrofrep sih dennod eh htab sih retfA
,noitarbelec lavitseF remmuS s’ssehcuD eht ta
?srotaripsnoc-oc rieht tuoba
,flesym fo lortnoc
erehw "elibmA eht fo sknaB eht gnolA"
?rotiart a osla ton saw dia sih ot emac revemohw taht wonk eh dluoc woh dnA
s'onlomS ekuD ?tolp siht fo nrael uoy did woH"
?ereh em tfel d'eh taht tegrof onraL riS dluoc woH
."yalP ta sdiaM neveS" fo rennam dipar eht ni meht deyalp eh rof
.nirg kciuq a mih dehsalf dna
,dias eh ”,semit ynam
.depip eh sa meht hguorht evow eh dna
,won tnedive saw nedraG eht ni draeh dah oilorB regna eht fo enoN
.detnemilpmoc yllaunitnoc saw eh
.daerht neklis wolley dna der ni srats gnitoohs htiw derediorbme ylivaeh
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
?mih erans ot redro ni evom ot oilorB gniwolla eh saW
,mrofinu yratilim
.onraL riS ,os hcum yreV"
,sediseb did srehto dna
.gnittips dna gnissih
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tcerid kaeps ot reh nopu edurtni yldrah
eh nehW .ecaps eht dnammoc mih tel dna stnemurtsni nwo rieht dellits ereht snaicisum eht elbat stnemhserfer a ot raen dellorts eh nehW
dewob eH .seton gnilbraw ,gnol lanif eht deyalp eh sa mih derewohs esualppa citsaisuhtnE
.nosirp sih fo sedis ruof lla yevrus ot ,llaw eht gnola dehcram dna denrut eH
"!rotiart a si drawetS ehT !nosaerT" gniyrc ,drawrof tpael oilorB
?noitangissa na rof ro peels ot
.siht sa hcus noitcnuf a ta mrofrep reven dluow eh wonk I gnos a ot gninepo eht htiw nageb eH"
"elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT" fo seton tsrif eht deyalp oilorB sA
mrofrep ot detivni saw
.tcepxe uoy taht rennam eht ni ton spahrep tuB ".os
,noitnetta ym thguac tahT
,pihsdneirf detivni taht hgual eltneg a dah eH
nodobort eht tub ,dekcarc ti sa demoob ydob eht dna degnawt dna deppans sgnirts ehT
.thguoht eh ,sworruf eht dewolp evah I .delevart
.eod eht dlot eh ",mih knaht I"
.mih dnuora lla saw rethgual dna
",su ot uoy thguorb dna uoy dnuof onraL taht saw ti suotiutroF"
.snavid eht fo eno no tas eH ".tnereffid
,dias raeb eht ",retsaM"
,dehgual dna deppalc eh neht
.pollacs rehtona gnirovas yb esnopser sih deyaled eh ,daetsnI
"revllapaK eht dna iztrO riS" gnimrofrep retfA
erofeb ylpeed dewob
fo trap lanif dna
.emac ti ecnehw morf duola derednow dna ,cisum eht fo noitatsefinam neddus eht ta demialcxe stseuG
.yrrow ot ni evag eh yllanif dna
.detpurretni rodassabma esenrotnuP eht
erow ehs tfel reh no dna
.hsiruolf a htiw gniwob ,ecneidua sih fo mialcca eht degdelwonkca eh gnos eht gniwolloF
dluoc eH ?yawyna ,taht od eh thgim woh dnA
.spirts rehtael deniwtne enif fo tleb a dna ,kaolc a
.htob uoy rof pu nward sredro evah lliw I dna
?sgnos eht erew tahw tuB"
"elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT" taht dezilaer oilorB
,no erow thgin eht sa seibbuc eht otni syaw rieht dnif dluow ynam woH
,nedraG eht ni nruojos sih denialpxe oilorB
loeb reh fo sgnirts eht gnikculp siomahc a
.ssehcuD eht dia ot sselesu eb lliw
,tnemom taht tA ".ecivres taerg a
oilorB .sregnif rehto reh no delkraps slewej erom llitS
.tnemhserfer fo ekatrap ,esaelP"
"?em rof mrofrep ot emoc won evah uoy taht epoh I eraD"
.spihs gnidiar tuo peek ot redro ni
.rotiart eht deedni saw tI
,eziromem ot tpmetta neve ton did xof eht taht etuor a gnola oilorB gnidaeL
.srotiart htiw dellif yldegella saw
.ytisoiruc ni detfil srae s’dnuoh detniop reh
,"yalP ta sdiaM neveS" sa hcus ,nwonk-llew erew emoS
,knurd saw eniw ,edam erew stsaoT
.yltrohs dereviled eb lliw rennid dna
,laperT ttaM yb ”nedraG eht ni sgnoS“
,"thgiL fo slooP eht ta naeN-ydneuT" diugnal erom eht ,gnos txen eht gninnigeB
,deraperp neeb sah htab A
.gninthgil gnilkraps dna rednuht gnillor htiw thgin eht gnillif dna gnitsrub sllehs dna stekcor
,etanutrofnU" .dias eh ",sey ,hA"
,gnos siht demrofrep eh sA
seganosrep demeetse rehto dna ,sreitruoc ,srodassabma htiw dedworc saw tI
,gniggaw liat sih ,stseug eht htiw dehgual eh dna detfil doom siH
,oilorB ot dias ehs
,sserd reh degnahc dah
.lla meht ot dias eh ",desaelp era uoy nrael ot em sesaelp tI"
.alehwib sih pu koot dna tleb sih otni kcab etulf eht dekcut eH ".gnineve
.erusaelp hcus uoy gnirb dluoc I desaelp ma I" .dias eh
.taem decips dna ydnarb raep htiw nedal saw htaerb sih dna
,mih gnihctaw saw ssehcuD ehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tnirp fo tuo yletanutrofnu won si hcihw tub
,ria eht ta deffins
.kcab delims oilorB
.rekaeps eht drawot denrut eh sa thguoht eh ,etrof ym ton si eugirtnI
tsriht sih hcneuq ot desuap
.stseretni ruo ni noitilaoc a egnarra tsum ocrabzU .sselehtenon
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
,mih hcuot ot deraef won eh fi sa
?llems fo esnes s’retto na si doog woH
.nihtiw stiawa tius gnimrofrep ruoY
.elbat a no rettalp eht tes ehs sa dias egap eht
.hgual kaew a htiw dias
,niatnuof eht fo rettalc ffo-raf
saw gnos eht taht timda ot dah oilorB rof
,llew sa mih dehctaw yldi onraL riS .desiar worbeye na ,mih dehctaw ssehcuD ehT
.ecaf sih no raelc dna eciov sih ni nrecnoc ,deksa eh
?gnihtyna wonk onraL riS diD
.tsaef s'gnineve siht rof gniraperp erofeb
.telbog a detpecca dna
ruf gniyarg htiw
retaw dellihc fo rehctip a htiw ,woble sih ta
.ecar ot nageb traeh sih ,niagA
,tsol saw eh moor-tserof eht retfa tub
.snodobort drawyaw dna ,sdraknurd
.efil ni esoprup elos sih saw tI
.cinut sih htaeneb esor selkcah sih dna
.ytinutroppo na hcus etaicerppa dluow I"
,derevocnu eb yam yrots repeed a taht tnemecnuonna s'oilorB retsaM yb deugirtni saw I"
,enotS ecneiduA eht delf dah
.mih erofeb rennid elbatceled eht ot nwod tas oilorB tfel d'ehs retfa dna ,dewob egap ehT ".ecnamrofrep
.seert eht otni delf oilorB ,delttar kcol eht nehW
.ecnamrofrep tsetaerg sih fo trap neeb tsuj dah ti dna
,"dessiM nediaM ehT"
.deksa ssehcuD eht "?ytsriht uoy erA"
.riaffa evol demood rieht dna ,aes eht fo nediam a htiw retnuocne sih dna ekuD a fo gnas
.mih edisgnola pu deldis ,retsam-dliug a fo niahc-eciffo eht gniraew ,raeb tneluproc A
".flesym sa hcus rerednaw a ot dnik oot raf neeb evah uoY
".reerac ym fo emca eht
.ti rof flesmih desruc dna ,lavres decaf-ruos eht gnihctaw neeb ton dah oilorB "!woN
,nedraG eht ni enola saw eh decnivnoc yllaniF
,rood eht no dnuop ot tsif sih desiar eH
dias olemaC nam eht dah tahW
,otsug htiw ni tes eH
.pu gnikool ,dias oilorB ",thgindiM"
.guj retaw a gniyrrac ,deretne onraL riS
.tsaoC lraeP eht fo sgnos eht fo ynam htiw railimaf saw ehs taht noissimda s'ssehcuD eht deredisnoc eH
elpitlum htiw wenk eh gnos ylno eht yldrah saw
# ".seod nodobort a sA" .dekniw eH ".niaga
.deilper oilorB ",sgnos ynam ,ynam
,seye eulb raelc reh ot gninruter elkraps gnicreip eht ,dias ehs ",dnA"
.robrah eht ot nwod dna nwot eht revo
.sevlesmeht tsgnoma gniklat
ssehcuD ehT .snoisrev etanretla eht fo eno daetsni gnisoohc
.dedaf dah noitatiga sih dna
,gnos txen eht nageb eh tub
.emac kconk rehtona nehw eldoon a pu gnipruls saw dna
.tekcor langis a gniraperp ,ecarG ruoY ,rewot eht fo foor eht no nem owt erew erehT"
.reh pandik ot tolp suoirafen a nopu delbmuts dna
.tsurt ot ohw wonk reven dluoc eH
.sciryl detalernu semitemos fo stes
ruoY" .nruter ni dewob oilorB dna
dnuos on ekam ot gniyrt ,seert eht neewteb tperc eh sa thguoht eh
.seert dna ssarg eht tub gnihton dellems dna
.rood eht ot drawetS eht deklaw dna doots oilorB ".ecneirepxe
dna enotS ecneiduA eht fo egde eht dehcaorppa dna navid reh morf esor ehS
.dias eh ",ytilatipsoh ni sevlesruo edirp
.denrael dah eh tahw dna
."elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT" fo enut eht ot tif erew sciryl esohw sgnos eht fo eno saw ti tuB .nommocnu
dna sdees eht tnalp tsum I
.rae reh otni ekops dna revo egap a dellac ssehcuD eht
2 traP ,laperT ttaM yb
".em dnuof egap ruoy lufetarg ma I"
.mih decnelis ssehcuD eht tub ,kaeps ot deirt taog ehT ".rewoT
detavoner dna tliuber neeb sah lusdayaP ehT"
.seimra gningiapmac htiw dellif
.rettalp derevoc a gniraeb eod deirevil a ot rood eht derewsna oilorB dna kconk a saw erehT
",noos emit yna rednaw ton deen uoY"
eh nehT .nur gnisir gninepo eht dekculp oilorB ,retsam-dliug eht ta kcab gninnirG
",em sronoh ecarG ruoY" .reh
fo noitaterpretni na rof etulf erevatiaC sih tuo thguorb eh ,alhewib eht no
.derevocsid sah eh tahw
,eciov reh gnillif rethgual thgirb
,ylsseldnim gninnur mih tnes evah thgim tnemevom ro esion neddus ynA
.deilper ssehcuD eht ",alotaK ,gninaem terces a dah hcaE"
.tolp ’srotiart eht trawht ot dluoc eh lla od ot deleets rehtruf saw tub
.niaga yaw siht ssap llahs I tub ,seod nodobort a sa ,no levart tsum I"
naicisum gnilevart eht oilorB ,emit tsaL
.kcab sih revo alehwib sih gnuls neht ,tleb sih otni etulf erevatiaC
,gnidurtorp elzzum sih fo pit eht ylno gnivael ,retaw mraw eht woleb knas eH
.nedraG eht ni devirra oilorB nehw snoitaraperp gnizilanif erew stnavres ehT
,mih raeh ot enotS ecneiduA eht ot detfird dah stseug rehtO
mih gnivig ,drawrof dekcirp srae reh htiw
.tnereffid on si ssehcuD ehT"
."puC-emocleW eht fo gnitfiL ehT" fo drohc tsrif eht kcurts dna ,dias eh
niag tsum I .eslup gnicar sih mlac ot deirt eH ".ytinutroppo
"?atsucleseD niatpaC si erehw ,woN"
.mosob reh ssorca gnillaf erofeb
.'elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT' fo noisrev etanretla eht dna 'yalP ta sdiaM neveS' fo etouq ruoy yb ta detnih ,egatnavda na dah sseltbuod I tuB"
# .ksat eurt s’thginot rof deraperp lla ta ton saw eH
.dnuof erew uoy dalg ma I .tcepxe uoy erehw dael ton od srodirroc semitemos dna“
,tnadrocsid dnuof yllausu srenrehtuos wollef drohc a htiw gnihsiniF
ni dekcol saw eH
,sraey ynam ni gnos taht draeh ton evah I"
yllaitrap neve nac I epoh I" .dias eh
.nageb xof eht ",ecarG ruoY ,em evigroF"
.gnis ot nageb dna
,kooltuo sih ni evitavresnoc saw onraL riS wenk I dna ,tneregilleb ylgnisaercni nworg evah slasoporp
.gninihs seye eulb gnicreip reh
.gnos eurt eht fo noitaterpretni etanretla na htiw dewollof eh dna
.ecneirepxe yranidroartxe na eb lliw thginot taht wonk ew
?dellac eh fi raeh enoyna dluoW
.rood a ediseb deppots gohegdeh eht
,ereh srebmahc evah uoY
mih erofeb melborp eht fo ytimrone ehT .krow ysae ton saw tI
.dias ssehcuD eht "?lleW"
,sgnirrae retsulc lraep erow ehS
.niaga ti ecifircas dluow eh dna
htiw gnola -- tnecs yhtrae ,yksum sih dna ,s’xof eht htiw level ylraen erew seye sih taht os daeh evissam sih derewol ylwols eH .sregnif kciht sih no sgnir evissam eht morf derettilg thgil-nretnal dna
.emac kconk wen a
.evom ton did yeht tub ,dellup eH .desolc erew yehT
,snoinapmoc deronoh ruoy dna uoy rof mrofrep ot ereh ma I ,ecarG ruoY"
,ymene na deredisnoc eb tsum enoyreve ,lusdayaP eht nihtiw sdneirf on htiW
,seert eht neewteb secaps eht otni derats
.noitceffa dna ssendas fo erutxim a htiw dellif seye reh ,mih ot denrut ssehcuD ehT
.mrofinu yratilim nacrabzU detaroced-ylhgih a ni taog a htiw gnikaeps saw onraL riS
.olemaC ,yas ot gnihton evah uoY"
.dellits rettahc eht dna ,deppalc ssehcuD ehT
.moor gnihtab a dna ,moordeb a ,moor gnittis a fo detsisnoc etius ehT ".thginot
,rodassabma eht rof denrut dna srehto eht gnoma kcab drawetS eht devohs oilorB
.raef dna noitatiga tniaf nwo sih llems dluoc eH
deniur sih evoba doots ehs ezilaer ot tnemom rehtona koot ti dna
.elzzum mih otni pollacs a deppop dna ,tuo dellac eh ",retnE"
,ssehcuD eht yb nettims saw
,tnemecalper a evah llahs uoY
.teef reh ta yal efink ehT
tuoba wenk drawetS eht tahw tuoba
sregnif sih tser ro
,eurt saw ti ,tra s'nodobort eht ot yek saw noitasivorpmI
",raw eb lliw erehT"
.ffo retteb on ,tiucric eht detelpmoc eh retal ruoh nA
.enigami dluoc eh gnihtyna naht lufituaeb erom llits saw tub
,ymaerd saw gnos sihT
",enivid thgim uoy depoh d'I tahw tsuj si tahT"
",lobmoR ,won drauG ecalaP eht fo niatpaC era uoY"
",gnos railimaf a ton si tI"
.rennid s’oilorB ediseb elbat eht no guj retaw eht tes drawetS ehT
.alehwib sih ta gnihctulc
,pit-liat ot eson morf derevihs oilorB
.tesnus tsap tsuj ,sruoh eerht tuoba ni snigeb flesti tsaef eht dna
,stsal ti ylno fI
.mih otni gnirob seye eulb-eci reh
.snoitaraperp ruoy dna rennid hsinif ot uoy evael lliw I
.tsap secnamrofrep dna slevart fo selat gnillet semitemos
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
",gnikil ruoy ot si doof eht epoh I"
.retsasid gnirb ylno dluow taht wenk tub
,tsomtu eht ot lliks sih fo lla niarts dluow siht tub
# .ecalap eht otni dna rood nepo eht hguorht decar
.ni denioj ylsuocuar dna sknird rieht desiar puorg eritne eht surohc eht ta dna ,gnas dna deyalp oilorB sa gnola deppalc tseug enO
.nruter ni daeh sih dewob
desopmoc saw gnos txen yM"
",onraL riS ,taht eveileb I"
.esrever ni gninepo eht ,gnos eht fo nur gnillaf ,lanif eht deyalp eH
deraeppaer eh nigeb dluoc hcraes a erofeb tub
,smra sih dessorc dna
ti ta deppis dna retaw fo telbog a flesmih deruop oilorB
,oilorB ot ssehcuD eht morf dekool alotaK .dias eh
"?raeh ot hsiw uoy ti si tahW"
.demrofrep eh gnos hcae gniredisnoc ,ylluferac denetsil I os
enut sti serahs deyalp oilorB retsaM gnos hcaE"
,sedaced owt ylraen ti deirrac dah eH .alehwib dekcerw sih gniees dehca eh ,hturt nI
.devirra stseug nehw wonk tub
,klis etihw erup saw trihs ehT
,elat a llet sgnos ehT
.dias oilorB ",ma I timda I"
.staebtraeh sih gnitnuoc
deveiler ma I tub ,gniht a hcus detapicitna ton dah I" .daeh sih koohs dna dehgis oilorB ".ti rehpiced ot eno ylno eht ton saw I tey dnA" .dias ehs
?wonk eh seod tahW
,ytiliba sih ni ecnedifnoc mih evag stirips denethgil sih tub
,nworc nedlog reh dedduts esiwekil slraeP
enid ot detivni era uoy dna
"!uoy geb I ,tiaW !retsaM ,oH"
.deilper ssehcuD eht
.esualppa citsaisuhtne otni tsrub mih dnuora puorg eht ,retsam-dliug eht yb deL
eht dna ekuD ehT' yalp ot uoy hceeseb I" .rediw werg gniyaws sih fo cra eht dna ,dennirg raeb ehT
.tnemom yna ta yrevocsid gniraef
.erofeb delbmessa reven evah I sa hcus sgnos fo etius a mrofrep ot dna
atsucleseD olemaC niatpaC suorotiart ehT
.dias eh ",ydaer ma I"
",yaw nwo ym dnif ot evah ot detcepxe I taht toN"
."yaD s'remmusdiM" ylthgirps eht yalp ot nageb dna
eno tahT ?rewoT ssaldniW eht si hcihW
raeh ot oilorB saw desirprus oS "....alehwib ruoy ,oilorB" .yltfos denihw ssehcuD eht ,nwod gnikooL
,neht erofeb gninaem sih nrael ot dedeen ssehcuD ehT
ecnamrofrep eht rof dnim sih raelc ot deirt eh ,navid eht nopu gnittiS
,"eriuqsE ,mugnihT riS" ro
uoy llet I nehw ssehcuD eht rof kaeps I
gniyaws liat reh
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
sih dekcut oilorB .gniwob ,dias eh
evah uoY" .gnignol dna yoj htiw peew yllautca thgim raeb eht thguoht
.noitnetta hcum gniyap ton saw eh taht dewohs ecaf retto dnuor sih tub
,rewolg ot deunitnoc rodassabma esenrotnuP ehT
.ezirp s'retsam sih mialc ot ereH .thguoht oilorB
.tseuqer s’retsam-dliug eht sa hcus ,os ssel erew srehto tub
,oilorB ot denrut ehS ".selttab ro
.ocrabzU fo gnir lacuD dlog dilos eht
.sesicrexe gniregnif sih hguorht gnikrow yb
.nwo ym dexat ylereves htuos eht fo sgnos eht fo egdelwonk ruoy ,llitS
kcab sih no tuo dial saw lavres eht tub
,redlo na doots ,onraL riS dniheB
.evoba raf erew swodniw ylno eht ,pu gnikooL
sihT".alehwib eht nrael ot detnaw syawla evah I"
.liava on ot ,meht tsniaga deniarts eH
,hpmuirt tnatcepxe ni gninediw nirg sih
.mih ot pu dettort egap gohegdeh A
",htuoy ym ot kcab em nekat
.ssehcuD eht nraw mih pleh ot seilla on eb dluow erehT .dediova dna
oilorB .htuom sih derevoc dna kcab dnah sih dellup eH ".modgniK
terces a hcus gnidnif tub ,ecrof fo noitacilppa reporp nopu detovip taht llaw fo snoitces suoinegni
!won
,nedraG eht fo tuo srood rehto eb ereht thgiM
,daeh reh dekcoc
",nodoborT retsaM ,teibnodrahS eht ot uoy dael ot em tnes sah onraL riS"
nrael ot ,deedni yltaerg ,desaelp ma I" .dias ssehcuD eht ",sevorg eht gnoma ecnellecxe ruoy fo selat gnirb stseug yM"
,olemaC ,onraL" .detuohs eh "!egassem a s'tI"
.etag tnorf eht morf xnyl eht
.ecuas etihw a ni seotamot deird-nus dna ,seldoon ,spollacs aes htiw delip hsid a derevocnu oilorB
,esrev dnoces eht fo elddim eht nI
.delkcuhc raeb ehT ".ti
.wenk oilorB tahw
.dias eh ",yad siht tsuj
.noitcudortni tuohtiw
.deksa ehs ",nodrap s'ecarG ruoY gniggeB"
,seidal dna sdrol ym ,emocleW" .ylpeed
,thguoht oilorB ,seog gniyas eht sA
daoR ehT" deyalp dna ,nirg a htiw dias eh ",no eunitnoc eW"
.thguoht oilorB
eht sediseb gnihton draeh eh tub
",cisum naht erom deiduts evah I"
?sedarmoc rieht no snug rieht nrut ylurt yeht dluoW
.seitlucaf s'oilorB dnoyeb saw
.reilrae deretnuocne eh tnecs yssarg emas eht dezingocer dna
.edisni deppart oilorB gnivael
.eciov llams a ni dias eh
,noos suoregnad emoceb lliw tsaoC lraeP eht gnola sdaor ehT"
"mirgaliV" neht dna
,tuoba gnilriws samora eht hguorht gnitros
.tsaef remmusdiM s'allerT ssehcuD eht ot
esaelp tuB"
,amora hcir eht ta delbmurg hcamots sih dna deretaw htuom sih ,yteixna sih etipseD
,lahsraM eht hcteF"
.nruter ni mih diova ot deunitnoc stseug rehto ehT
.yawa meht koot neht
,mih ta delims ehS
.retsaM ,srebmahc ruoY"
emoceb sah tsaef ruoy ta mrofrep oT" .dias eh
.liat reh depparwne ten ralimis A
.dias ssehcuD eht
.raen llits erew srotiart eht taht tnih yna rof eson dna srae sih deniarts eh dna
?tnemurtsni sih tuohtiw nodobort a si tahW"
,elihwnaem eht nI“
.gninrom siht ylrae aeS ediW ediW eht ta kcab neeb dah
.kcurts noitaripsni
,erofeb deciton ton dah eh taht srood
,ssehcuD eht rof devom nam dlo eht mih drawot denrut daeh yreve sa neve dna
'ydneuT-aeS
,liat dna enam dediarb yletarobale na htiw eram llat a htiw gnikaeps saw olemaC
.ten dekcedeb-lraep a htiw derevoc dna ,won hgih delip saw riah nedlog reH
.yad siht emit yna ta dah eh sa ylpeed sa dewob oilorB ".yhtrow meed uoy eno dnif uoy fi ,noitcelloc nwo s'lusdayaP eht morf
.eil a saw taht tuB
.yldam gnikcilf liat ,gnicar dnim ,srood eht erofeb decap eH
,yrd saw htuom sih dna deremmah traeh siH
.gnola gnis ot deunitnoc emos dna ,esrev dnoces eht nageb eH
".em detcartsid niatnuof ehT .hguoht ,nedraG eht fo edistuo saw tI
,yllacificeps em dna ,ocrabzU enod evah uoy tub
eh dna dedualppa puorg delbmessa eht
".siht sa hcus tca na ot gnipoots meht ees ton did I tub
.elbat stnemhserfer a ot deppets dna niaga dehgis ehS ".htob
,teibnodrahS eht ni noitaraperp lanif eht gnikam era stnavres ehT" .doots eH ".dnuof
ssehcuD ehT "?nodoborT retsaM ,won woH"
roiretxe s'remrofrep sih htaeneb egap eht fo nruter tfiws eht ta tnemtnioppasid sih dih eH
,dedurtni yltnatsnoc
",suoreneg ylgnideecxe si ydaL
,gnos dipar eht deyalp eh sa kcen s’tnemurtsni eht nwod dna pu welf sregnif siH ."neabaiE morf
,seert eht fo tuo
navid a no alehwib sih tes oilorB
.nedraG eht fo tser eht ta tuo derutseg eH ".erusaelp
?em dessim evah yeht dluoc woH
,slatrop neddih erew ereht spahreP
,stnemurtsni rieht denut snaicisum fo riap a rood eht tseraen elbat eht ediseb dna
",gnos txen siht wonk lla lliw uoy eveileb I"
.deliaf evah I .thguoht eh
.yevnoc ot gniyrt saw eh yrots repeed eht dezilaer dah ssehcuD eht taht kniht ot
,'elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT' retfA"
reh nraw ot skees eh woN
,seilla sah tub ,setatS lacuD eht gnoma etirovaf on si anrotnuP
,lla retfa nugeb sah tI
"?sgnos esoht morf lla ta egassem yna naelg uoy did woH"
.etag s'nedraG eht dna flesmih neewteb elob a gnipeek syawla dna
,yltnedifnoc ekops eH ".hcraes
,dehcaorppa gnitiaw-ni-seidal s'ssehcuD eht fo enO ".nwo
.etius detcocnoc sih ni deniamer sgnos erom owt ylnO
,klis etihw dna eulb fo sreyal fo
saw
.tes saw gnos eht hcihw ni ,smodgniK nrehtroN eht fo cisum eht morf gnilyts deworrob tI
”nedraG eht ni sgnoS“ fo trap lanif dna
,"efiw dna ,dliuG hcus-dna-suhT eht fo eman-reh-stahW retsaM"
.dehgual retto ehT ".yruxul
.ocrabzU spahrep ro ,anilosaC evlovni dluow yrots eht naem ot taht koot I" .dias ssehcuD eht
.eciov raelc a ni
.srood eht dehcaorppa eh
,tleb sih denethgit eh sA
.thginot ssendnik reh yaper
"?emuserp I ,oilorB retsaM era uoY"
,sloof srovaf eniviD eht
,ti dleh dna eton lanif eht kcurts eH
.enut lanigiro na gniraeh fo ytlevon eht ta esor noitasrevnoc fo zzub ehT ".'semihC
,ylwols eh did neht ylnO .erus eb ot
.gnol ton saw tiaw eht ,mih rof ylikcuL
.knard dna elzzum reh ot telbog a detfil ehs sa koohs sdnah reH
.remmah ot nageb niaga ecno traeh siH
.rehtona yb deliart dna
,nodoborT retsaM ,gnipoh saw I"
.tuo dellac eciov a "!nodoborT
,eurt erew sdrow sih tuB
won eh eno eht naht rehto htap on ees dluoc eh tub ,noitan reh fo esnefed eht nigeb ot
,ecneloiv eht morf yawa degrus dworc ehT
.elpoep htiw dedworc won saw aera elohw eht dna
,noitingocer desirprus ni
,nedraG eht derednaw stseug fo rebmun elbatius a tlef eh nehW .no os dna
desiar eb ot ,meht neewteb gnurts saw niahc a wenk eh dna
,ecnaraeppa detcepxenu sih ta dethgiled ,deppalc dna dehgual yehT
.dnah thgir reh gnisrun saw ssehcuD eht dna
,gnos eht fo noisrev railimaf tsom eht gnis ton did eh tuB
.noitatiseh tuohtiw niaga ti od dluow I tub
.allepac a gnignis htiw gniyalp detanretla eh
"?em rof sksa ohW .ma I" .deksa htuoy eht
.dezilaer neeb sah uoy ni ecnedifnoc ym taht
.tsevrah eht rof epoh
.lavirra wen siht tuoba suoiruc ,reh dniheb derehtag srehto eht
.regna dna ytip fo erutxim a htiw taog eht gnidrager saw ohw ,ssehcuD eht sdrawot denrut eH
.yruxul hcus ot dael netfo ton seod nodobort a fo efil ehT
,tevlev kcalb fo erew kaolc dna sehceerb eht dna
,elims citegrene s'nodobort eht gniraew ,deyalp eh sA
.alehwib sih htiw tuons sih htaeneb onraL riS kcurts eh ,thgim sih lla htiW
.enut a peek ton dluoc eH
,tuo dellac ehs "!devirra sah oilorB deugnot-ragus ehT"
,sexoF  :SEICEPS ni derutaef seirots neetriht fo eno ,laperT ttaM yb
,deunitnoc skrowerif eht meht evobA .tnemurtsni
."hguone" era erehT
.tonnac I fi raef fo keer lliw I .thguoht eh
.tuo gnignir otarbiv
,esirprus ni depsag ehs
.drohc a gnikirts erofeb alehwib sih gninut stnemom emos tneps dna ,tleb sih otni kcab etulf eht dekcut eH
.niaga dehgual drawetS ehT
.gnineve s'remmusdiM enif siht uoy niatretne ot erusaelp tcnitsid ym si ti dna
.derednow oilorB ?olemaC taht sI
.ecalap eht hguorht etuor eht naht sthguoht sih fo erom deipucco dah ssehcuD eht taht timda ot decrof
",uoy rof hctaw ot segap eht lla detcerid sah onraL riS" .dewob egap ehT
"?efil a ot derapmoc
kcen reh dnuora spool lareves edam slraep fo epor gnol a dna
.daeh sih dekcud tnaegres ehT
.ssendas htiw yvaeh eciov reh ,dias ehs
",ecnamrofrep ruoy erofeb tisiv ot troffe tseb sih ekam lliw dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
?yalpsid skrowerif eht dna thgindim litnu gnol woH
mih dehctaw ssehcuD ehT .tnemecnuonna sih gnissucsid ,sevlesmeht tsgnoma derepsihw emoS .yltnetni mih dehctaw stseug ehT ?yrots repeed eht gnirehpiced ni deeccus ehs dluoW ?dnatsrednu ehs dluoW .raef ni tnap ot detnaw eh dna deremmah traeh sih tub
,raef nwo sih tub gnihton dellems dna draeh eH
.gniltsirb ylerab liat sih dna
,mih erofeb nosaert sih tuo yal ot ,ecaf sih ot semirc s’nam eht tuohs ot detnaw
.eciuj fo telbog a ta deppis eh ,scipe cioreh taerg eht fo eno gnimrofrep retfA
.derongi eb tonnac sihT"
,gnas dna deyalp eh sA
layarteb gnidrager sdallab cigart yltsoM"
dnoces eht
.taorht sih deraelc eH
.tsaef eht fo tirips eht ni ylluf ,dehgual dna devaw yeht dna ,puorg eht tfel eh ,gninnirG
.teksum sih fo ttub eht htiw drawrof niatpaC eht deddorp srehto eht fo eno ,emit emas eht tA
.dluoc eh tnecs dna ,thgis ,dnuos yreve ni gnikat
retsaM" .noitcesretni na deredisnoc eh sa derettum eh
.snoitpo sih gniredisnoc ,ylwols knard eH
neesnu niamer ot derised eH
”nedraG eht ni sgnoS“yojne esaelP
I dna ,retsasid a eb lliw ecnamrofrep yM
",tops eht etiuq neeb evah tsum tI"
.retaw hserf fo guj a em gnirb
.secils egnaro htiw derovalf
.ekil uoy sa gnol sa emoclew era uoy dna
.noonretfa taht desived dah eh snur gnimihc eht otni gnarps neht
.mih dnuora ecaps ytpme eht ta gnirewolg