,dnalrednow a
dna ,"dessiM nediaM ehT"
.gniylper erofeb detatiseh oilorB
.amevroF fo yletal ,orgeliP oilorB retsaM..."
”,onraL riS rof egap a dnes ll’I“
.yawa nelots saw htaerb sih ,ruoh na ni emit dnoces eht rof dna drawrof deppets oilorB ".enotS
I dna oreuG retsaM
,rucco ot siht rof stseretni ruo fo lla ni si tI
.romuh tuohtiw delkcuhc olemaC ".sredart
,srennab lavitseF remmuS thgirb htiw gnuh erew eseht
fo stseug eht gniniatretne
",egats a hcus dah I evah reveN"
"?noitativni mialc uoY"
”nedraG eht ni sgnoS“
sah ehs ,truoc ta selpmaxe rehto tuohtiW"
,alecsetelaM ad ,orgeliP
.draug ta ecalp sih demuser namteksum eht sa oilorB dehcaorppa eH
,sgel trohs sih no yawa gnittort ydaerla saw retto eht
gniwollA ?enigami uoy naC“
s'ssehcuD ehT .tleb sih morf gnuh taht mraerof sih fo htgnel eht tuoba gab a dettap eH ".etulf
".esuoh tneiciffe yrev a smees lusdayaP ehT" .dias eh
.ssehcuD a ,esac siht ni ,ro ekuD a erofeb tey reven tuB
.tevlev tsenif fo kcalb yssolg eht dna ,swons retniw-dim fo etihw tnaillirb eht
.gnineve tsal uoy gniraeh retfa evisuffe saw onraL riS
,moor eht fo retnec eht denil snmuloC
,ekops eh erom eht deeps ni gnisaercni ,mih dniheb htrof dna kcab tpews liat s’oilorB ”.dluohs nodobort doog a sa ,ecarG ruoY ,srehto lareveS"
",noonretfa siht srettam rehto ot dnetta tsum I" .thguoht eh
roloc fo sehsalps feirb ylno gniwolla
,"elibmA eht fo sknaB eht gnolA"
.setatS lacuD eht
elttil dewohs ehs tub
,etag tnorf dedraug ylthgil eht ekiL
,anilosaC fo emaD ,ocrabzU fo ssehcuD
.yawa welf neht dna ,tnemom a rof derevoh ,mih dnuora yaw sti dnuow eeb a dna
,retrauQ sroliaS eht morf yaw eht lla gniklaw naht retteb raF
,seirots ni tnenimorp ,enecs larotsap lanoitidart a saw tI
,mih erofeb deltsub nehctik ehT
.senob sih otni ylteews delttes taht
# .seert eht gnoma deraeppasid ylkciuq dna
onraL riS ",tuohguorht daerps eb lliw knird dna dooF"
.eno eht wonk uoY
.dias eciov a ",oilorB
.moor eht ni ekat ot kcen sih gninarc llits ekaw sih ni oilorB ,srood eht ot dessorc onraL riS ".dnoyeb
.dias eh ",elur reh rednu suorepsorp si ocrabzU"
.dias eh ",setatS lacuD eht fo sgnos eht fo ralohcs a ylsuoivbo
,mih ot nuS eht saw ehS .suoires erom neeb ylerar dah oilorB ;yremmulf
,noitanitsed s’oilorB detiaw llih eht fo pot eht tA
,eraperp ot ybbuc ybraen a otni dekcud eH
.llih a no egalliv tnatsid a dna swodaem ot gninniht tserof eht dewohs rehto eht elihw
",onraL riS ,sselhceeps ma I"
.rodirroc eht nwod yaw emos ydaerla
dna sroloc lavitseF remmuS eht ni
retsaM" .kcen s'alehwib eht
,anrotnuP ekil lla ta toN .setatS lacuD
.dworc yadiloh eht otni dna mart maets eht morf nwod deppets oilorB   2 fo
.nortap sih drawot kcab denrut xof ehT
?alehwib eht sediseb
,yawa neht dna daeherof sih ot dnah eno gnipeews ,ylpeed dewob oilorB ".noitnevnoC
",namow luflliw a si ssehcuD ehT"
".egde raf eht ees tonnac I" .deksa xof eht "?siht si gib woH" ".stbuod
,nedraG eht fo llaw raf eht gnola
.ecalp ni yldilos lla erew sterf revlis eht dna
draobterf eht no sregnif sih fo pat-pat-pat tfos eht saw dnuos ylno eht ,niatnuof eht fo elkcuhc ffo-raf eht sediseB
,levart tnatsnoc eht dnatshtiw ot ydrah eb ot dah tnemurtsni
,era hguone tuB" .dias olemaC
,ytirojam fo neethgie eht ot naht sraey evif-ytriht nwo sih ot resolc raf
-- erusaelp sih dna -- ytud sih osla saw ti tub
.dias ,olemaC ,eciov rehto eht
.setag ecalap eht hguorht dessap eh sa dias eh
gnihtyna yalp uoy oD"
.deklaw yeht sa deksa oilorB
stbuod on evah I"
,ssehcuD eht fo taht sa dlo sa ylraen si tI“ .dias onraL riS
.krow eht fo rednow sih desaercni ylno erutan sa gnissap ecifitra sihT
.gnitacixotni saw ecnetsixe
,gniltsur a emac ecnelis raen siht otnI
enihsnus tnaillirb eht tsniaga
?noitasivorpmi nA"
,thgir eht fo pit eht hguorht
.enon detceted tub
.gnimrasid dnuof oilorB yaw a ni dehctiwt sreksihw sih dna ,delims onraL riS
,dehgual ssehcuD eht tuB
.reh morf detfird retaw surtic fo tnecs ehT .ssehcuD eht htiw eye ot eye flesmih dnuof dna ,denethgiarts eH
teem reve uoy diD
.noitnevnoC lanoitaN eht fo droL tsriF dna
.ecivres ruoy ta ma I dna
.nac eno sa ,nac eno tahw snrael enO"
.erutifmocsid sih ta desuma ylsuoivbo ,liat reh dekcilf ssehcuD ehT ".evisserpmi
.hguorht gnikeep yks eulb htiw sevael sa detniap gniliec eht dna
.erohs eht ot resolc tpek evah sehcnarb rehto
nehT" .delims drawetS ehT
,drow hcae htiw gnikrej dna gnicnuob liat reh
.tnemesuma htiw mih dehctaw ohw ,onraL riS ot denrut eH
?yltnecer denaelc
.detisiv evah I seirtnuoc emos naht reildneirf raf dnA"
",si ti deednI" .dehgual oilorB ".lla retfa
,toofrednu tfos dna kciht saw ssarg eht tub
.reilrae naht ,reirgna ,redrah tub ,eciov s'onraL riS saw tI ".eno
,llew yrev reven hguoht ,lrig a sa
.rebmahc detluav ,daorb a otni oilorB del onraL riS
",erutan gnortsdaeh s'ssehcuD eht fo gniniartsnoc eht dnA"
.oilorB ot rettel eht denruter eH .elims a tsomla
.ti rof retteb lla era ew dna ,ocrabzU fo
,sgnirts eht ta yltfos dekculp eh sa htrof dna kcab dekcilf pit-liat siH
,nemekip erew owT
eh nehT .ligis eht denimaxe ylesolc eh sa tnaegres eht morf ,ytud enituor fo
.stluassa fo rebmun yna ot elbarenluv eb lliw ocrabzU ,eno tuohtiw seid allerT fI"
.lortnoc sih tsniaga dereviuq liat s’oilorB
.seciov wol fo rumrum tcnitsidni eht neht
,flesym rof ti nees ton evah I tub
.tsaef yna ta lanoitidart saw "puC-emocleW eht fo gnitfiL ehT"
.sehcnarb esoht fo eno yb denwo
.sriats emoceb ot sa peets os werg semitemos dna
erew olemaC siht dna drawetS ehT
.elob deneziw erom dna regral a fo noisserpmi eht evig ot
.nedraG eht otni nwod delbmuts oilorB
.niaga ti daer neht
onraL riS ,drawetS eht fo noitativni no emoc"
.daeh sih dekcud eH ".ti
erolpmi I" ".'semihC esuoH lliH'
.dias eh ",onraL riS ,uoy knaht I" .dewob xof ehT
,pih tfel sih no ssaltuc a erow ohw
”,neht ,elur dluohs noitnevnoC lanoitaN eht taht su llet
.robrah eht morf llih eht debmilc syerots ruof dna eerht fo sgnidliub defoor-elit ,dehsawetihW
,shtap on erew erehT .ecruos sti ot dnuos eht gnikcart ,taht dna yaw siht gnileviws srae ,seert eht otni deklaw eH
"?ti saw ,esuoh-polf on saw tI
.gniklaw edepmi ot ton hguone trohs tub
."evoL yM ,seugaeL derdnuH enO"
,saw ylniatrec sih dna
,derewsna oilorB ",nodobort
..." .gnikaeps saw onraL riS
.dias oilorB ",drol ym ,enoN"
.revewoh ,rebmahcetna eht
eht ",edis a no secap derdnuh enO"
.ylecin pu naelc I taht
.eb yam yeht eurt woh rettam on
.ton naht netfo erom reippah pu sdniw
,eniviD eht fo ecarG yb
fo sehcuot dedulcni tub
,woleb tuo daerps
.oilorB retsaM ,noonretfa dooG"
,demihc yeht taht os sgnirts eht ta dekculp yldipar neht
,orgeliP oilorB retsaM ma I" .deksa eh
"?lusdayaP eht ta uoy evah ssenisub tahW"
nemteksum fo sriap erom owT
,secneidua sih eguag ot denrael ylkciuq nodobort a tub
.lareneg ni noitautis eht ta saw ti spahreP
.raey a ynam ni draeh ton evah I yrettalf suoicadua hcuS" .dias ehs
.snoisserpxe dekcohs rieht revoc ot tub
gnitsaef htiw dellif erew dna
”.sevresed eunev a hcus ecnamrofrep eht htiw truoC lacuD eht tneserp ot regae ma I"
,ecarg emilbus htiw reh tuoba stnadnetta fo duolc eht morf denrut ehS
,tnemelpmoc a sa ti esu dluoc ,gnignis dna gniyalp sih otni ti etaroprocni dluoc eH
",yltneserp ,tseb ym ta ton ma I"
",os em fo nekops sah drawetS eht taht raeh ot erusaem dnoyeb desaelp ma I"
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
gnos fo sehsad ro
”nedraG eht ni sgnoS“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
”.yad ysub a s’yadoT
,wodahs ni depard saw esle lla dna
enirhs tneicna na fo sniur eht morf gniwolf retaw
.enotS eht ni nedraG ehT"
.tserof eht sdrawot ,tuo gnidir saw ytrap gnitnuh A
”.lla retfa ,lavitseF remmuS eht s’tI“
.amora ynirb lausu s’retto eht ot derapmoc krad dna yddum
,ydob retto gnol s'drawetS eht no
,gnimaelg seye reh ,oilorB ta delims ehS ".ti
derussa eb ,rettel eht ni debircsed taht sa hcus noissimmoc a rof gnimlehwrednu uoy ot mees I fI
.emit taht revo snwot erocs owt ni gnimrofrep
,nosaert s’onraL riS trawht ot seganam oilorB woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
".siht
.sgnirts eht dellits neht
",krow taerg a si ti deednI"
,epols-pu ecaf s’xof sih denrut dna
.gnitsaef s’thginot rof gniraperp ylregae erew snezitic reh dna anilosaC .dennirg eH
,temleh leets lacinoc dna
.lrans tnelis a ni delruc pil sih dna ,daeh sih tsniaga talf yal srae siH
,rednels dna llat
,ereh tsaef eht fo tsom dneps lliw ssehcuD ehT" .dias onraL riS
.ti gnola ylluferac seye sih dna sdnah sih nar eH
.retaw eht dnif ot dedeen eh ,tsriF
.derongi eb yltsom dluoc seiddib gnirettit eseht wenk eh dna
seye sih dedleihs eH
rednimer a saw siht
",ecarG ruoY ,erusaelp tsetaerg ym si tI"
,seveels retrohs htiw ,noihsaf nredom
.setatse rieht ta selbon erofeb mrofrep ot snoissimmoc nekat netfo dah oilorB ,noitatuper elbarovaf a htiw eno sa dna
dehsimelbnu llits saw
.lusdayaP eht hguorht mih del drawetS ehT ".lahsraM
.ti ot uoy evael lliw I
.sdraug fo raelc esiwrehto saw draytruoc eht tub
,stnannep dna gnitnub wolley dna ,egnaro ,der htiw gnuh erew steerts ehT
.dias ehs ",sraey ynam ni stsaef remmusdiM tsenif eht fo eno etapicitna I" .gninediw elims reh ,daeh reh dekcoc ssehcuD ehT .decnemmocer gnirettit ehT ".deripsni ylurt saw krow ym tub ,emas eht od ot elba eb
.retsgnuoy eht retfa ffo derats oilorB sa dias onraL
,oiradnizteV otni
.ecalp eht tliub taht pihsnamstfarc dna lliks eurt eht dezingocer eh hguorht mih del onraL riS sA
,reppoc dehsinrub fo roloc eht ruf keels reh
.dias ssehcuD eht
oilorB taht hguone esolc
,taeh eht dna bmilc eht morf gnitnap saw oilorB
,lavitseF remmuS eht si tI
.deklaw yeht sa dias onraL
.ton ro ti ezilaer ew rehtehw
.llaw raf eht detanimod srood egral fo riap A
# .rodirroc eht nwod raeppasid euniter reh dna reh dehctaw neht
,pu kool ton did drawetS ehT ".detisiv
.kaeps dluoc oilorB erofeb detcejretni onraL
si ecarG ruoY" .snoitautis gnignellahc ni
.derewol eb lliw niahc ehT .robrah eht ta ,rewoT ssaldniW eht evah ew dna
,tnelis erew stnadnetta eht woN ".flesreh
,ti raeh ton did oilorB erom gnihtyna dias onraL riS fi dna
riS ",ytirojam reh ecnis os neeb reve sah tI"
,sllaw raf dna raen eht htob no sretsalip gnihctam htiw
.lavitseF remmuS eht fo xamilc eht gnitarbelec
.derob erew sdraug eht ,gnihtyna fI
.smra depirts ylrub sih ni ksac-ela na gniyrrac rehtaf eht dna
.uoy ot ti wohs lliw I ,emoC"
,hO" .sdnah reh deppalc dna ,ytraeh dna lluf
.esneffo gnittimmoc morf mih gnivas
,ria eht deffins oilorB
neeb tius gnimrofrep ruoy saH"
nedraG eht ni repeed eno rehtona ot detacoler eH
.reh dniheb deyaws yllausac liat reh dna
.tsal eht si ehs tuB"
,drohc a kcurts dna alehwib sih gnulsnu eH ".eniviD
riah fo sevaw deyenoh dna
.setatS lacuD eht tuohguorht lavitseF remmuS eht fo ycaciled erutangis a erew taht seirtsap surtic eht fo amora eht thguac oilorB
"?nopu nepo ti seod rednow tahw"
xnyl a htiw denruter draug eht setunim wef a nI
",ralimis gnihtemos od ot decrof neeb sah tpokenstelasT fo gniK eht taht si gnidnatsrednu yM"
yojne esaelP   .tnirp fo tuo
.spets eht dednecsed eH .dias drawetS
,seye sih fo tuo riah fo sdnarts gnol emos dehsurb oilorB
"?flesmih astelaM oreuG retsaM
.yalp ot sgnos deredisnoc eh ,dehcraes eh sA .suoirolg saw tI
.lla retfa ,lavitseF remmuS eht si tI .nus remmusdim eht ni osla saw llihpu klaw eht ,noitutitsnoc ym rof tnellecxe saw ti elihW"
.teibnodrahS eht ni gniknird dna
.esion luftcepsersid a edam onraL riS
.tah a gniffod fi sa
.denialpxe
",tbuod on evah I taht fO"
almahsiT fo gniK eht dlot ma I .sredliub ecalap eht fo
.sresuort eulb revo stekcaj etihw dna spac eulb derehtaef ,llat htiw ,nemteksum erew owt rehto eht tub
.seert defael-daorb erutam fo evorg a ot del neerg derucinam a spets eht fo toof eht tA .dnuora dezag dna spets eht otno tuo ylgnitlah deppets oilorB
,seibbuc eht deredisnoc oilorB
.evisserpmi dna peed si egdelwonk ruoY"
,allerT ot uoy tneserp I ,oilorB retsaM
.dednet yletairporppa neeb sah tius ym ecnis sthgin ynam oot neeb sah ti raef I
,semoc drawetS eht erofeb owt ro eno htiw ffo ekam dluoc I fi rednow I
.liat kciht ,gnol dna smra dna sgel trohs sih htiw
.gniraeh s'oilorB dnoyeb
,edistuo nemteksum eht fo esoht ot ralimis mrofinu a erow
.etag eht dehcaorppa dna ,liat sih koohs
.ytlayor gniniamer ylno eht erew elcnu reh dna ehs
.dias eh ",oilorB retsaM
.gab gnilevart sih ni kcab rettel eht decalp oilorB ".yllautneve
eht ylno si siht fI"
.ezingocer ton did oilorB eciov a ,detarepsaxe
onraL riS ",olemaC ,revo noos si ssenisub siht dalg ma I"
.evorg eht nihtiw peed morf emac retaw gniwolf fo rettahc ehT
eldi ton tub ,suoicadua ylerus dna ,erus eb ot ,saw ti yrettalF ".raey
",os od ot uoy
nwod dna pu sregnif sih dekrow eh sa thguoht eh
.drol ym ,ecnatsissa hcus etaicerppa ylurt dluow I"
si aeS ediW ediW ehT
.elzzum sih tilps nirg s’oilorB
.nees evah I yna ekilnu si moor sihT" .dias eh
,ralupop syawla erew esohT .seoreh dlo eht fo sgnos edulcni ot oilorB dednimer ti dna
.reidlos eht ot gnineve suoiverp eht deviecer d'eh rettel eht dereffo dna gab gnilevart sih fo tekcop a otni gud eH ".noitcudortni
,thgiarts doots rodirroc eht ni nexiv ehT # .dlrow eht ni
.ti fo tsom eht ekam ot dednetni eh dna
.thgindim ta tsaot lanif eht litnu yleerf xim ot
".ecnamrofrep ym gnisived ma I ,ydaerlA
,deppots riap ehT ".stluassa
ediw gnignah elzzum dna talf srae sih ,yldiputs deknilb oilorB ,tnemom a roF "?ydaerla
evisserper taht ot revo reh nrut dnA
,teibnodrahS eht ni enolA
,tnemtnioppa ym rof etal eb ton tsum I
",terces niamer llits dna elbissop eb ton dluoc gniht a hcus wonk uoY"
.gnitcartsid oot rettahc s’niatnuof eht dnuof gnol erofeb tub
,enots sti fo egnit eulb tfos eht rof deman
"?thgindim ta nigeb lliw tI
,erofeb naht rekciht neve saw noitatiga s’onraL riS .ylraelc meht llems dna raeh htob dluoc
taht dnif ot ma I sa desaelp sa ylraen ton tuB" .dias eh
.dehcaorppa drawetS eht sa doots dna ,thguoht oilorB
,cisum sih yalp ot setatS lacuD eht fo seitic eht neewteb gnilevart ,nodobort a sA
deedni ro ,wenk eh sgnos dlabir tsom eht fo eno fo noitnem reh ta
.tsaef eht rof hcaorppa sih gnisived
,niaga ecno ylpeed dewob oilorB .dias ehs
.yad ysub a si yadoT" .dias xnyl
yletanutrofnu won si hcihw tub
.seert eht otni elihw a rof derats oilorB
,ssorca secap derdnuh eerht
saw ehS .elims gnimoclew a dereffo ehs sa
.flesreh nuS eht fo ratava na yb dednetta eb lliw
.ylsuoires oot ecalap eht dna yhcuD eht nihtiw noitats hgih sih ekat ot raeppa ton did eH
,sretsalip eht neewteb
stros fo siad a erofeb egreme
enut trohs a gniyalp retfA
.eniviD eht ot no dessap eh erofeb meht deretsam ylluf reve su fo net naht erom on dna
.kcab dna sredluohs reh ssorca decnuob
,namow luflliw a htiw gnorw gnihton si erehT ".gnortsdaeh nworg
.erom delggig seidal ehT
.nihtiw deltsen hcneb ro navid a htiw hcae
lusdayaP eht dehcaer eh emit eht yB
.amora yssarg yvaeh a htiw ,detatiga ssel saw tnecs s’rehto ehT
alhewib sih dehctih eH
.enots eulb siht fo elddim eht ni ecaps neerg a
,llaw eht gnola ehcin a otni tes hcneb a ot oilorB del ehs sa dias namow eht
.weiv s'oilorB morf deraeppasid dna etag eht dnoyeb werdhtiw draug ehT ".ereh tiaW"
",llaw nrehtuos eht gnola si ecnartne 'stnavres ehT"
".won ,eman ni ylno gnik si eh dna
.reh rof ,efil ym fo ecnamrofrep eht siht ekam lliw I
yal spets enotsgalf fo tes a nwod dna srood eht dnoyeB
,dluoc eh sa llits sa gnipeek ,gninetsil ,htaerb sih dleh eH
,eciov suoiciled reh ni sdrow hcus dereviled allerT ssehcuD eht sA ".gnineve
,egatellocéd reh desopxe taht kcen ediw a
.ecalap eht drawot bmilc ot skcart mart eht dessorc eH
"?og I erofeb snoitseuq yna uoy evaH .gninnigeb eht morf evres ot detcepxe eb lliw uoy dna ,tesnus ta snigeb tsaef ehT"
,rethgual elfits ot ton desiar sdnah
"!dlrow eht ni erehwesle siht ekil gnihton si ereht yleruS"
,steerts eseht no srelever rewef dessap eH
.sredart ruo rof noitcetorp retteb ,laoc fo ecruos eruces a
,epols-nwod kcab dekool dna
!onlomS girp
.snoitisop rieht hguorht meht dekrow eh sa
.deksa tnaegres eht
.retal ereh eb lliw ehS
.pal sih ni alehwib sih ,navid eht fo swollip tfos eht otni deltsen dna
devom yeht sa tuo dedaf eciov s'drawetS
,yb dessap sbuc owt sih dna regit A
liat deroloc-tessur sih tuo koohs eH
.neffits onraL riS was oilorB ,eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuO
.dias drawetS eht
.roolf eht no eldnub eht pu dekcip dna retto eht dniheb morf deppets egap a dna
,tsaerb rieht no rewolfnus a erow sreidlos eht llA
,dias ssehcuD eht
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,egailof kciht rieht htaeneb seibbuc niatnoc ot delaever erew stekciht ehT
,seert eht gnoma gniraelc a ni niatnuof eht dnuof eh erofeb sgnos nezod a naht erom fo tsil a delipmoc eH
.drawrof deppets ,xof a ,nemteksum eht fo enO
,dnopser ot woh tuoba erusnU
,ecarG ruoY ?mih wonK"
",'alecsetelaM ad' ,emanrus ruoY"
,kcart sti gnola yawa degguhc mart eht sa thguoht eh
riS ",snigeb tsaef eht erofeb llew ydaer eb lliw tI"
.daeh sih fo pid feirb a denruter drawetS ehT ".stseug
?'yalP ta sdiaM neveS' eb owt esoht fo eno dluoW“
,mih morf gnisir noitatiga eht llems dluoc oilorB
.sevorg eht nihtiw decalp erew selbat dna
.sraey ynam ni pu eno nekat ton evah I dna
.did yeht sa netsil ot deniarts oilorB dna
"?ew dluohs ,yaled erom yna esuac ton dluohs eW"
snisuoc ruoy ot stnemilpmoc ym evig
,roolf eht ta gnirats ,revo dehcnuh deklaw eH
.dias onraL riS ",sey ,skrowerif eht htiW"
,reilodnab daorb a ni slotsip owt
".yadot ,ecivres ruoy ta si lusdayaP ehT
.hcneb eht tsniaga roolf eht no kcap gnilevart sih gnittes
.swodniw dna setag nepo morf epacse ot
ti eltitne dluohs I ,yam I fI
.lahsraM eht ot dleifelttab eht fo egdelwonk sa nodobort eht ot tnatropmi sa si
,srood niam s’lusdayaP eht ot pu sriats fo thgilf daorb a erofeb draytruoc ediw a deretne oilorB setag tnorf eht hguorhT ".si ti deednI"
.esor srefinoc fo dnats a ,ecnatsid eht nI
secaps eht detaroced senecs tserof sllaw eerht nO
.thginot tsaef s'ssehcuD eht yalp ot ,atsaciseR
.ralucitrap ni eno on ot ,dias eh
,ocrabzU kcurts revef eht retfA"
",krow drah fo laed taerg a hguorht elbissop edam saw tI"
".oiradnizteV eht morf yawa dlrow a smees retrauQ sroliaS ehT"
"?gnos taht si tahW"
.stnemal 'srevol htiw sa esoht htiw deffuts sa saw eriotreper sih dna
egats eht fo egdelwonK"
ehT "....langis eht tA .seilla
"!stseretni tseb reh ni si tI" .dias eh
"?aeS ediW ediW eht ta eb ot emoc uoy did woH"
.selbategev hserf htiw gniwolfrevo ot dellif
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
ylkciuq kniht ot osla denrael nodobort a tuB .draeh reve dah
.sroloc lavitseF remmuS eht htiw gnuh
.slraep rof nepo deirp snacrabzU eht sretsyo eht fo eno ekil ,flesmih no ni desolc dah retto ehT
,seutriv reh lla dna nuS eht fo noitarbelec
mra reh no teksab eht
oiradnizteV eht fo snoisnam nwot ehT
denepeed nworf sih tub
gnihtaerb sih dewols eH
sregnif sih deppans drawetS ehT ".dednet
erehT .draytruoc eht dessorc eh sa thguoht oilorB
,redluohs rieht revo gel-evoob lluf a gniraeb sretsgnuoy eht fo hcae
etulf erevatiaC eht deyalp I"
.yllacirtaeht dehgis allerT ssehcuD
,sdrawnwod derats llits nam rehto ehT
.kcab dna drawnwod denrut
.elohw deniamer ti erusne ot
,deifsitas saw eh nehW
.anrotnuP fo ekuD gniyllub ,sselromuh ,suopmop tahT
.lusdayaP eht ot emocleW"
,niaga klaw ot nageb owt ehT
"?elbissop siht si woH"
"?su htiw ylluf drauG eht sI ?ydaer nem ruoy erA"
,anrotnuP htiw snoisnet eht fo gnisae nA
.tnemom eht fo nrob
.serohw eht tuoba gnos taht pu thguorb ehs..."
.mih delzzad ylhguoroht dah sllaw etihw s’nwot eht morf gnitcelfer thgilnus thgirb eht dna
,yaw rehto eht gniog htap sih dessorc namow knuks gnuoy A
,rettel eht ta decnalg xof rehto ehT
.anrotnuP rof erac ton did eH
.reverof seibbuc eht gnoma evil dna seert eht ni flesmih esol ot detnaw eH
.tsaef eht fo thgilhgih a eb lliw ti
.sdne enil ehT" .deksa eh
",enotS ecneiduA ehT"
",nemeltneg ,thginot litnU"
.ti daer ton did tub
.emitefil a fo ytinutroppo eht htiw em detneserp evah uoy ,onraL riS" .dias eh
,mih detnahcne ecalp ehT
ssariuc lanoitidart ni dalc
”.ereht deyats evah uoy taht garb ot kees yam yeht ,ecnamrofrep s’thginot retfA“ .dias eh ",llahs I"
.nihtiw sehcuoc denoihsuc eht dna
"?nrevog ot srenommoc
,woleb steerts eht ekiL
",eerga ot evah dluow I"
1 traP ,laperT ttaM yb
.nedraG eht revo tuo dekool drawetS ehT
.sffuc sih no sgnikram s’tnaegres dna
,tnegeR sa nicserB droL htiw ,neetxis ta ssehcuD denworc saw ehS
.denediw seye
pooh dlog llams a
eh dna ,ecalp taht etah ot nosaer erom neve dah oilorB woN
.tsaef s’thginot rof gniraperp ,htrof dna kcab gnihsur stnavres dna skooc
.hcus yas ot mih rof elbissopmi ylraen ti edam snoitats rieht ni ecnereffid eht tub
.etulf erevatiaC
.yllautneve emoc lliw drawetS eht dna ,rettel ruoy tneserp dna ereht kconK" .dias eh
,mih ot dereffo neeb dah ytinutroppo dnarg A
.gninrevog naht rehto snoitapucco reh evig lliw
,swal yrautpmus on ,ereh slortap tnatsnoc on era
dluohs tnemurtsni sih htrow nodobort ynA .ecarG ruoY ,em elbmuh uoY" .niaga dewob oilorB ".detroper yllaitini onraL riS naht delliks erom raf era uoy taht egduj I
ylediw gninnirg drawetS eht dewollof oilorB ".thgindim
”nedraG eht ni sgnoS“
elur fo nedrub eht fo
.nirg yls a htiw deksa ehs ”?deednI"
.nrocs htiw deppird eciov sih dna
otlartnoc gnorts ,raelc a ni dias ssehcuD eht ",oilorB retsaM"
.nwod tas neht ,alehwib sih gnulsnu eH
,sehcnarb rieht sbir tluav eht htiw
,epac trohs a htiw ,delyts yllanoitidart saw sserd neerg reH
.ssehcuD eht morf taht edih dluoc eh woh derednow oilorB .tnecs retto ynirb sih detaretilbo ylraen dna
,epoh ylno thgim I
.eson sih dellif selbategev dna stiurf epir dna ,sdaerb dna ,staem fo samora eht dna
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,hcuot sih htaeneb htooms saw ydob pordraet ehT
,lusdayaP ecalaP lacuD eht
,niar yam ti hcihw nihtiw
,onraL riS ,kaeps uoy sdrow etanutrofnu hcuS"
redluohs sih no rehgih
dluow allerT" .suortsasid eb dluow noitasrevnoc siht gniraehrevo elihw yrevocsid taht gniwonk
",oilorB retsaM ,gnineve siht ecnamrofrep ruoy ot erusaelp htiw drawrof kool I"
,teibnodrahS eht ot emocleW"
,ytsejam sti ta kcurtsbmuD ".uoy
"?thginot os od uoy lliW
.nworf ereves a ni depoord sreksihw sih
.rebma lufituaeb a ot dega dah hsinrav fo sreyal eht dna
,seuqinhcet alehwib euqinu sih em thguat eH
deniwtretni sknurt lareves htiw netfo ,htworg tserof larutan fo noisulli eht etaerc ot
,esoppus I ,suoucipsnoC .ereh rewot eht morf ffo og lliw tekcor A"
.regna gnisir sih fo lortnoc peek ot gnithgif ,denetsil eh sa hteet sih dnuorg oilorB
sti sa yltfos degnob tnemurtsni degnirts eht dna
.sgnirts eht llits ot luferac ,tsehc sih ot tnemurtsni sih dehctulc eH
,seert eht fo ynam neewteb gnurts erew snretnaL
.oilorB retsaM ,os yas uoy raeh ot desaelp ma I"
.nrut ni hcae gnikculp ,sgnirts thgie eht denut eH
.rettel sih denimaxe ,ssertsiM nehctiK eht sa decudortni lerriuqs elamef a neht ,reidlos rehtona rood ’stnavres eht tA
.dnah hcae ni eniw fo elttob a ,epols-pu gniyrruh gohdnuorg a
,daeh sih evoba erom ro sdor owt doots tsellat eht fo spot ehT
elihW" .sriats fo thgilf a pu oilorB del dna renroc a denrut eH ".aes
noisiv eht dna" ,dias eh
.dias ehs ",snoititep dna ycamolpid lla ton si lusdayaP eht ni efiL"
sti fo egdelwonk yrev eht
,anilosaC ni riaffa lamrofni na si tsaef remmusdiM ehT"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
riS ",gnineve siht tsaef eht erofeb sserdda ot snoititep evah seod ecarG ruoY ,llacer I fi tuB" ".nac
,ton esoppus I ".lusdayaP
.taht dezingocer reidlos eht erus saw eh dna ,hguoht ,mottob eht ta tnenimorp saw ligis s'drawetS ehT .lla ta daer dluoc eh fi derednow oilorB
.ecalaP lacuD eht dnuora retrauQ hgiH eht
ym dna alehwib ym htiw ylno levart tub
.noitcudortni fo rettel a evah I
.em nopu llew tcelfer ton lliw tI .thguoht eh
.tolp siht trawht ot dluoc eh tahw od ot denimreted
,ti daer dna rettel eht koot xnyl ehT ".od I"
.oilorB derongi sdraug rehto ehT
,tsaef remmusdiM eht
,ti teg ot skrow dna ,stnaw ehs tahw swonk ohw namow A .thguoht oilorB
eht ",os si ti erusne ot tseb ym od I"
uoy taht geb I" .dias oilorB ",yldrah toN"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.deltsirb ruf siH
,drawetS eht ot pu hctac ot deirruh oilorB ,ssehcuD eht retfa gnirats tnemom rehtona retfA
.oilorB ot noitnetta sih denrut
.robrah eht ni gnibbob spihs gnilraep eht fo yna fo slias eht gir ylluf ot hguone egral ,ocrabzU fo
,evom ton did dna
,srood eht dekcolnu dna yek thguorw-ylenif a decudorp retto ehT
,noitnetta ni drawrof dekcirp erew srae reh ,tniop etaciled a ot werd elzzum reH
.kcen s’alehwib eht nwod dna pu decar sregnif s'oilorB sa edacsac a ni gnillaf seton
.ybbuc eht ni neddih
srae elttil sih dna kcab sih dniheb ylthgit depsalc sdnah sih htiw
sriats eht fo pot eht dehcaer yehT
?loohcS astelaM eht fo rebmem a era uoy naem ot taht gniterpretni ni tcerroc I mA"
,sexoF  :SEICEPS ni derutaef seirots neetriht fo eno ,laperT ttaM yb
.detlaxE hcruhC on ylniatrec dna
.siht sa hcus esuoh a ni ecnamrofrep rof tifnu owt lanoitidda na dnA .sciryl tnereffid rof ydolem eht esu taht erom owt dna" ,dias eh ",ti fo snoisrev neves wonk I" .delkcuhc oilorB "?'elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT' wonk uoy oD
.sdrohc wef a deyalp eh
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,laperT ttaM yb
anilosaC fo ytic eht ta
degaruocne era stseug eht dna
.enimreted ton dluoc oilorB ,ssehcuD eht ta ro mih ta saw ti rehtehw hguoht ,gninworf saw retto ehT
,serratihs ressel dna retaerg eht dna
.dias eh ",suolucidiR"
.nettims saw eH .ega ro
"?thginot ereh dleh eb lliw tsaef eht lliW
namow lufituaeb tsom eht erofeb saw eh rof
,snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup
,sdnah rieht dniheb morf mih ta delggig stnadnetta s'ssehcuD ehT ".ecivres
.tnemeticxe sih gnitcelfer
.etag nepo eht gnidraug sreidlos ruof eht ta detniuqs eH
,tnemhcated fo tnecs emas eht thguac oilorB
.delkcuhc drawetS ehT ".nni
.taorht sih ni thguac htaerb sih dna
,nroh deralf eht ,murd robmat eht wonk I“
sihT" .yks remmusdim raelc eht saw mih evobA
,drohc tsal eno kcurts eh
,srewolfdliw llems dluoc eH
.deilper oilorB ",ris ,os deednI"
.drawetS eht ta gnicnalg ,dias eh
.deggurhs drawetS ehT ".retal
,snrettap tcartsba etarobale ni dedaeb ecidob a
.tsaef s'thginot ta gnimrofrep eb lliw uoy wonk ot desaelp ma I"
tub si sihT" .dias eh
ssorca lla lavitseF remmuS eht fo lobmys eht
.deye-ediw ,dnuora dekool oilorB
,mra ni mra elpuoc taots a
ton seod allerT fi neve ,stifeneb ynam evah lliw onlomS ekuD ot egairram" ,deunitnoc eh ",tneve yna nI"
.rettel eht derefforp oilorB
,gnithgil tesnus rieht gnitiawa
,tnasaelpnu si tI" .dias
.dennirg nodobort ehT
,tsurtsid ro raef fo sngis elatllet rof ,dluoc eh sa yllausac ,ria eht deffins eH
,ecarG ruoY ,noitasivorpmi nA"
.stseug reh dna ssehcuD eht rof mrofrep ot ytinutroppo eht rof lufetarg ma I"
,elbissop sa ylkciuq sa ecudorp ot krow lliw onlomS hcihw ,rieh nA" .dias onraL riS
denethgiarts eh nehw dna ,esnopser ni dewob oilorB ".oilorB
,dias eh ",gnineve tsal aeS ediW ediW eht ta uoy gniraeh retfA"
,apmapaC ordnA oilorB retsaM ma I" .dias eh
ragus sti tsol eugnot ruoy saH ?oilorB retsaM ,tahW
"?seid ehs nehw neppah lliw tahW
,ecnatsid eht otni gnidecer
.demialcxe eh "!levram a si
.meht ezingocer yletaidemmi
dna tuc renif a fo tub
,dias drawetS eht
.retal sraey owt enorht eht ot gnidnecsa erofeb
.kcab sih kcurts ydob wolloh
.tleb sih no xob noitinumma ro pac llat eht tuohtiw dna ,lairetam
.stbuod ym evah I os
,esnopser on dah oilorB siht oT "?neht tahW
.sthgin wef tsal eht detnuah d'eh sevrahw eht drawot
".ecalp eht fo erusaem eht niag ot
”.gnineve eht gnirud erehwesle reh retnuocne yam uoy hguoht ,sutats tsehgih
,srood eseht deknalf
.rekciht werg tnecs detatiga sih dna
emod elbram a htaeneb nedrag dihcro dna sutol a sah
.thguoht eh ,gnineve eht ni retal spahreP
.ti gnidnuorrus ytic occuts etihw eht ot tsartnoc ni
,eciov rehtona dias ",od I"
.doots eh erehw morf egde raf s’evorg eht ees ton dluoc eh dna
.nehctik eht hguorht ffo dehsad tloc eht ,drow a tuohtiW
,srelever yaD s’remmusdiM gnignis dna
.ecnelis sih ot drawetS eht tfel eh dna
.evirra thgim eh nehw wonk t’nod I tub“
.eno dnah-thgir eht no dehsup neht
htiw srae reh fo srenroc rewol eht morf delgnad sgnirrae pord-lraeP
settesor htiw dednalrag liat etihw-dna-kcalb gnol reh
gnir lraep-dna-erihppas egral a erow ehs dna
.snretnal gnidnats-eerf dna ,selbat dna ,snavid htiw degnarra dna spets tnorf eht sa enotsgalf emas eht fo tliub
."rednuhT eht dna lletnaM riS" yb deriuqer soiggepra detacilpmoc eht no dekrow eh emit a retfA
ot seert fo dnats lanif a hguorht dessap riap ehT ".elbattegrofnu
s'nodobort A .egamad yna rof ti denimaxe dna pal sih ni tnemurtsni eht deldarc eH
lacimoc dekool ti oilorB oT
ecneicsnoc eht era uoY
,nedraG eht ni dleh eb lliw tsaef ehT
.kcap s'oilorB ot derutseg eH ".tsaef
,sekuD eht fo ecivres eht deretne rehtafdnarg-taerg ym
,llirg nehctik eht rof ydaer
",rieh na evah tsum yhcuD ehT" ".yrassecen tub
,mra dehctertstuo sih fo htgnel eht doow krad ,kcen ediw ehT
tpmeknu dna dliw raeppa ot hguone gnol
.dehsinif eh sa gnippalc dna gnihgual lla erew stnadnetta reh dna ssehcuD ehT
,pu dekcit htuom s'tnaegres eht fo renroc enO ".ylecin
",yranidroartxe saw tahT"
erised uoy tcepxe I .mrofrep lliw uoy erehw ,nedraG eht ot uoy wohs lliw I" .dias drawetS
.ssehcuD eht worhtrevo ot gnittolp
.elbattegrofnu eb lliw ecnamrofrep ruoy erus ma I
"!nodobort retsam a fo eugnot deragus eht
yhcuD eht fo galf eulb-revo-etihw eht welf rewot lartnec hgih sti morF
.detfil ylgnimees doom krad sih ,delkcuhc drawetS ehT
.seenk reh evoba gnisir triks eht ni stils dna
detcerid dna deniart ylluferac
,ocrabzU fo drawetS ,atsaciseR onraL
.pots thgim traeh sih hguoht sa tlef eh dna ,dias ehs
,noilleber a saw erehT" .dias oelmaC
,rehtegot tsaoC lraeP eht gnilevart raey a flah tneps
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA   .nac eh fi
..." .devloser seciov eht dna ,dnuos eht hctac ot srae sih denrut oilorB ,ylevitcnitsnI
."nuS eht rehtruF" dna
.ecnamrofrep sih gnirram ,gnirednaw elihw ti ssorca elbmuts ton os dna noitacol sti wenk eh fi ylno tub
,dias oilorB ",yawyrtne
seert sa raeppa ot detniap dna detnemanro
,rodirroc rehtona nwod denrut dna
.regnif xedni thgir reh no
,"eniW s'remmusdiM" sa hcus sgnos ,llew sa cipot ralupop a saw lavitseF remmuS ehT
.htap a raelc ot gnignalc lleb
.derettilg seye s'ssehcuD ehT
,sah ohw enoyna htiw nekops ron
.nni taht rof dloh I meetse eht no
traeh sih ot oilorB decreip ,tiw dna rethgual htiw gninihs ,seye eulb-eci reH
ruo ot elbakatsimnu tub ,robrah eht ni segrab eht morf gnisir yalpsid niam eht htiw
.aes eht htiw detaicossa neeb evah ew emit taht lla rof dna
,sllaw etihw rieht dniheb snoitarbelec rieht tpek
eht ",yllautnevE" "?yllautnevE"
,"ollerG dna anemreF" dedulcni eh os ,edart s'nodobort eht fo yatsniam a erew srevol tuoba sgnoS
nepo erom eht fo eno saw ocrabzU taht
.tsaef s'thginot ot noitidda tnellecxe na eb dluow uoy wenk I"
,dias oilorB ”,wonk I“
.mih dlot oilorB
,reworran hcum erew tub
.gnilims ,deilper allerT ssehcuD
.loop wollahs a otni llihnwod
.thguoht eh ,ereh semoc ehS
”,anilosaC ni eno dlo na si ylimaf yM"
,niart dedacorb ylivaeh a dna
,dewollof stnadnecsed sih dna
yllautca erew ,lavemirp dna tneicna tsrif ta gniraeppa ,seert ehT
?ssehcuD eht htiw noitasrevnoc sih retfa "elirtopmaC fo srevoL ehT" yalp erad eh diD
.onraL riS ot neht ,oilorB ot tsrif daeh reh denilcni ehS ".tsaef