.srood tnorf eht ot eunev eht hguorht tnew ehs ,tixe tseraen eht tuo gnikcud fo daetsnI
.s’nivaG sa yffulf sa tsomla saw liat sih dna hsulp dekool srae ralugnairt gib sih tub
detsiwt yzzI ”.sdneirf fo elpuoc a htiw dnab a detrats tsuj I
.sevren reh no etarg ot detrats noitommoc dna klat eht
”?gnorw s’tahw eeS“
lausu eht no kcab llaf t’ndid ehS
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.tfahs retaeb ehT“
.puorg lrig a uoy dellac taht gninrom siht weiver a was I“
”.thgie ta si llac suB
.moor neerg eht ni setamdnab reh htiw dexaler annA ,wohs rieht retfa ,thgin taht etaL
.deneppah tsuj tI
,dnab eht htiw saw ehs sselnU
”.gniyalp fo hgih eht teg t’nod uoy tub seod dnab eht naht sruoh esrow neve evah uoY
saw annA taht wenk ettolrahC ylno dna ,ylwoj elttil a ,deye-tfos dna
dluoc ehs erehw ,dnif ot depoh llits ehs pohs eeffoc eht fo thguoht ehS
.dias ettolrahC ”,emit fo ytnelp tog ev’eW“
,eivE dna enimsaJ rof erew snoitseuq reh fo lla tsomla ,yletanutrofnU
,sub eht tseraen rood eht ta gnitiaw snaf syawla erew erehT
,nivaG ot dias neht ,moor neerg eht dnif ot tfel dah dna
.noh ,esoprup no gniruot tiuq t’ndid I“
.tuo uoy raew taht swol dna shgih eht s’tI“
,wahS .C.K yb ”kcehC dnuoS“
naem I“ .noitseuq reh esarhp ot yaw thgir eht
.etunim gnissap yreve htiw
.dereehc dnab ehT
.moor neerg eht tfel ehs sa gnilims flesreh thguac annA
ni er’eW“ ”.thginot knub s’enoyreve ni ssip ot gniog m’I
.snoitseuq s’retsacdop eht derewsna yeht elihw srehto eht htiw doots annA
,elpoep yb dednuorrus reh tpek taht boj a htiW
.retsacdop eht ot kcab denrut ydaerla dah eh tub ,mih deknaht annA
,snoitats oidar lacol morf now sessap egatskcab htiw snaf erew meht fo emoS
.ecno rof yenom dah yllautca ehs dna llew yllaer enod dah smubla wef tsal rieht tub
”.uoy erofeb remmurd lrig a nees reven d’I
.teehs yad s’worromot deliame ydaerla ev’I
.sesuoheraw fo hcnub a ekil dekool tahw dna
”?hguoht ,gniyalp ssim uoy t’noD“
,yzzI oT“ ,etorw annA
,dias reweivretni ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.reh derehtob esle eno oN
.yawa elim a flah tuoba s’ti ,hO ?mH“
.doom yhtlif a ni saw ohw ,remmurd eht yb tem eb ot ylno
.looc reh peek ot ezeerb a fo hguone tsuj htiw ,edahs dna nus delppad hguorht
”?krow rehtie lliW .sladep owt dnuof I“
.epyt s’eivE yletinifed saw eH
*** .ehcadaeh a gnitteg saw ehS
.seitic erom snezod dna ,dnaltroP ,revuocnaV ,tiorteD ,asluT ot
nekops-tfos saw eH
”.skcub gib eht uoy yap ew yhw s’tahT“
.emoh og ot detnaw tsuj ehS .eromyna ettal a tnaw neve t’ndid ehS
,naem I .oot remmurd a m’I
,egatniv dekool koob hpargotua ehT
”?raf os neeb ruot ruoy s’woH“ dna
ylsuoicsnocnu ylbaborp—
.reh ta dekool neve eno on tub
.tnemeticxe ni liat reh deggaw ehs sa dewollib taht triks kcalb htgnel-eenk a dna ,oga sraey xis ruot tsrif rieht morf trihs-T a erow god ehT
,sknaht reh deremmats yzzI
.kcurt a htiw ti revo nar neht ylbissop dna
.boj ym did dna nwod daeh ym tpek tsuj I“
.ti teg dluoc ehs revenehw edutilos devarc annA
wahS .C.K yb
,ni thguorb dah nivaG doof revetahw eta dna reeb knard yehT
”mubla wen ruoy tuoba su lleT“
.doog tlef annA tnemom a roF
.letoh eht dehcaer ehs nehw
.slanoisseforp erew yeht dna
.sthgil esuoh thgirb eht rednu gnimaelg ,egatsno resir a no saw tik murd reH
.kcahw fo tuo tneb si buh retaeb eht tub ,ti deganam uoy woh wonk t’nod I“
.elbuort hcum oot ekil demees ti tuB
.yppah eb dluow stnerap reh tub
.srae eht dnuora pmad llits tub won desserd
.neerg odacova dna wolley dratsum ni seisiad dezilyts htiw detaroced revoc sti
.enohp sih morf pu gnikool tuohtiw dias reganam rieht ”,enif er’eW“
.elims gnimoclew a otni ecaf reh deloohcs ehS
skcits reh barg ot detnaw ehS
.lla retfa ,gnineve taht
,reyalp ssab s’dnab eht saw ettolrahC ”?emit fo stoL
”.weivretni taht rof ereh si retsacdop ruO“
,spup owt htiw deirram ylippah saw kcaJ ecniS
.ylteiuq dehgis annA
,nrob saw tsedlo ym emit eht tuoba pu ekorb dnab yM
,drawkwa na ni elkna rehto reh dniheb toof eno
.gig wen a dnif ot yrruh t’ndid I os
,won thgir tserof eht ni gniklaw saw ehs dehsiw ehS
”!puorg lrig a su dellac yug gnidnecsednoc sihT
moor neerg eht tfel ehS
.erac t’ndid dna ni erew yeht ytic tahw erus t’nsaw ehS
?eman ruoy s’tahW“
,rehtegot gniklat dna gnihgual ,edistuo doots llits elpoep fo spuorg wef A
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,gnihtyna ro sratsrepus t’nerew yeht ;tnagavartxe gnihton—
,eivE ,tsiratiug rieht htiW
dnif ot gniyrt ,noitartsurf ni wap a devaw ehS
.nwod reh looc pleh dluow taht hguoht sa
.sgnikram nrohgnorp s’eivE fo sepirts ecaf kcalb eht dehctam
,reggum a fo daetsni tuB
.reh ta eciwt dekool eno on
”,uoy deltrats I yrros m’I“
.serutcip fo elpuoc a deppans nivaG dna—
.kcehc dnuos dessim yehT
”.thgin yreve cisum taerg ot netsil ot teg I dna sserts woL
”.tuo eno siht yrt ,yakO“
.dehgual eH ”.t’nac dna kcaJ yppup erutcip ot gniyrt m’I ?taht saw nehW“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
.srae revo-deppal
.tnurg a htiw pu gnitteg ,dias kcaJ
emit tsrif eht rof skcitsmurd pu gnikcip ,yzzI ekil slrig derdnuh a fo thguoht ehS
*** .ylteiuq dias annA ”,haeY“
,setarip pihsria ydal fo elpuoc a tuoba seirots trohs fo noitcelloc a
.saw annA sa reweivretni derruf-nedlog eht morf tnereffid sa
.lrans a htiw dias enimsaJ ”,emit eht llA“
.eno wen siht sa llew sa did mubla txen rieht fi ,rehpargotohp dnab a etar ylbaborp d’yeht ruot txeN
”?tuonrub eht htiw laed uoy did woH“
.hteet reh lla dewohs ehs ylediw os gninnirg
gnitnev enod erew yeht litnu kcab gnuh annA
.mih gnisol ksir ot tnaw t’ndid ehS
”?kcor ot ydaer uoy erA !asluT oooolleH“
.remmurd eht tsuj saw ehS
.derednaw dnim s’annA
”.puorg lrig a er’ew ylneddus remmurd elamef a tog ev’ew esuaceb tsuj tub ,did yeht fi moor eht fo tuo dehgual eb d’yehT
.hguorht yawflah tuoba egap knalb a dnuof ehS
.niaga deppots sub eht nehT
:gnitirwdnah denoihsaf-dlo ,tnagele ni noitpircsni na daer annA ”.ebyam ,srotcA
,setunim ytnewt revo rof ciffart llitsdnats ni neeb dah sub ehT
emit siht elims s’kcaJ
,buh eht ta dekop annA
.raeg ni ti tup revird eht sa dekrej sub ehT
.deksa annA ”?VT ro oidaR“
.meht denrut annA nehw esool tlef segap eht dna
.krims a htiw dias eivE
.htob meht koot annA
.elims yrw a reh evag kcaJ
lley ot boj reh t’nsaw tI
.flesreh etipsed detseretni ,deksa annA
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,wahS .C.K yb
srae xnyl detfut-kcalb s’enimsaJ
,yklis morf kcen reh nwod sevaw tnagele ni gnillaf ruf reh
”.hteet ruoy rof dab s’tI .eivE ,eci tae t’noD“
.gniK deepS a saw ladep tsrif yM“
”.enif si tfahs retaeb ehT“
.deirrac syawla ehs nep eiprahS eht tuo koot dna
.seveels repap elttil ni sdrac yek tuo dellup dna
.tnemtnetnoc yraew a otni wollem hgih lacisum s’wohs eht tel dna
.lworg ot naem t’ndid I .eruS“
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.flesreh ot sgnileef reh tpek ehs
.ruot txen eht no eb t’ndluow ehs ebyaM
”kcehC dnuoS“:yojne esaelP
.rehtie ,nwo reh no dneps dluoc ehs sruoh ton dna—
,deerb etanimretedni fo god a saw eH
.retaw ot dehctiws annA ,reeb eno retfA
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.delims annA .erutseg suovren
.feiler htiw edistuo deppets annA
”.gnol eb t’now yehT .ydaer gnitteg llits era srehto ehT“ .dias annA
.meht ees tsael ta ro dnab eht ot klat ot gnipoh
.reh ta decnalg eH
”?thgir ,yad eht ni kcab gniruot fo tol a did uoY“
.doog saw eh dna yalp mih draeh d’ehs hguohtla
”.eraps a evah dluohs I ?tneb ti sI“
.won ruoh na flah tsomla ni devom d’yeht naht rehtraf tub ,ecap gniklaw ylerab—drawrof desae tI
.reh wohs ot ti dewercsnu eH
.detrats tes rieht litnu steerg-dna-teem dna sweivretni gniod eb d’ehs ylekil erom tub
elbat eeffoc derettab eht no pu teef reh tup ehS
?gnimmurd tuoba gnihtemos etirw uoy dluoc ,mU .yzzI yb og I“
”?netfo edutitta evissimsid fo dnik taht teg uoy oD
,reh dednah noil niatnuom eht koob hpargotua dezis-tekcop eht detpecca ehS
.meht diova rehtar d’ehS
,yawykS si koob tsetal reH
.relooc ylthgils saw ti erehw egnuol tnorf llams eht otni demmarc erew reganam ruot rieht dna dnab ehT
.dnab elohw eht rof noitseuq etilop lanoisacco na htiw
.tnemtneser fo ezalb neddus reh ta desirprus saw annA
oga shtnom xis esuoh lautca na thguob d’ehS
,ebyam ,ecivda dooG
.dnab yob a acillateM sllac eno oN“
esruoc fo tub—kcehc dnuos a deen yllaer t’ndid dnab eht os ,ni delaid gnihtyreve dah werc dnuos eht daor eht no skeew eerht retfA
:ecnetnes rehtona dedda ehs noitatiseh s’tnemom a retfA ”.taeb“
.lezterp a otni yleritne flesreh detsiwt noil niatnuom eht erofeb kcab koob hpargotua eht dednah dna
.tinu gninoitidnoc ria eht rednu dekan krats gnidnats
.ylduol dewehc dna htuom reh ni gnihtemos deppop ehS
”,kcehc dnuos ssim ot gniog er’eW“
”.elamef yllaicepse ,remmurd rehtona teem ot doog syawla s’tI“
.erus rof s’taht ,nrob erew uoy erofeb gnoL“
.dedaf saw serutangis eht no kni ehT
”.egdub t’now ti tub ecalp otni kcab ti gnihsup deirt I
”.epoh I ,ydnaM toN
nwot ni snaicisum wollef ro sretomorp ro sper lebal erew emos
tuo snrut ti dna retal sraey wef a dnab s’dik sih rof hcet ot em deksa dneirf A
.daeherof reh debbur annA
.dehcaorppa tevlev ni sreltna htiw kcub llat A
.kcul tuohtiw ,noitasrevnoc a rof hguone teiuq erehwemos rof dnuora dekool annA ”.esruoc fO“
,dias kcub ehT
,dekcol saw ecnartne ehT
”?hpargotua ruoy teg I dluoc ,mU“
.dias ehs ”,ladep wen a pu kcip dna tuo nur nac I ?nwot ni erots cisum a ereht sI“
”.nnI syaD a ees uoy litnu klaw dna daor niam eht no thgir nruT
.nivaG ot denialpmoc eivE dna enimsaJ
.reh ot tuo ladep eht dleh eH
.naf 1# ym ,ydnaM oT“
,ybraen erehwemos ettal a dna klaw trohs a rof emit evah llits d’ehs ykcul saw ehs fI
.ten.wahsck ta
,egatsno tik reh dniheb tas ehs nehw syawla sa dna ,enorht eht otno dils annA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.flesreh yb teerts eht nwod deklaw ehs ,suomynona ylippaH
,naicinhcet murd  reh ,kcaJ nehw deveiler saw ehS
.yalp reh was yeht esuaceb
.suoegrog saw regnis eht ,yhcuorg dna ytaews nevE
,eson s’annA ot sllems fo noitanibmoc gniticxe na thguorb ezeerb ehT
,wonk t’ndid ehs ,tahw gniod—boj laer a teg dna yleritne cisum morf eriter d’ehs ebyaM
etatsretni enal-evif eht dnoyeb noziroh talf eht ta dereep ehS
.dias annA ”,ecin taht saw gnitirwdnah ym hsiw I“
.dniheb esolc eivE htiw ,dlrow eht ni ygrene eht lla dah ehs hguoht sa meht ot pu dednuob enimsaJ
.eciov s’raeb eht ni eton ynihw eht ta detatirri flesreh dnuof annA
,sgel reh hcterts ot klaw gnol a rof emit evah t’ndluow ehS
.wohs eht tuoba klat ot yb deppord elpoep dna
,reirret a ekil sriah draug yriw dah ruf etihw dna nworb siH
.ciffart gnivomnu eht ta derats dna wodniw sub eht tsniaga depmuls annA
”.traehteews ,htiaf eht peeK
.era elpoep esoht fo yna ohw wonk t’nod I .pohs euqitna na ni ti dnuof I ,oN“
.detnaw annA tahw ton tub
”.emit eht lla derit os er’uoy yhw rednow dna sdrawretfa hsarc neht ,egatsno tuo luos ruoy ruop uoY
taoc elap reh ni skaerts kcalb diviv eht dna
,annA“ .werc daor eht fo yaw eht ni gnitteg ,egatskcab dnuora derednaw dna
.tol a ecitcarp I tub era uoy sa doog sa ton m’I
yllufreehc gnimmuh saw ehS
.decrof ylthgils saw nirg s’xof ediw sih hguohtla ,lufreehc dednuos nivaG ”!era uoy ereht
.enizagam cisum a fo revoc eht rof gnisop eb llew sa thgim riap eht reh ot txen gnihcuols
”.haey ,tib riaf A“ .mih deksa ehs
.raey a fo trap retteb eht rof eunitnoc thgim ruot eht ,sdworc doog gnitteg tpek yeht fI
.mih htiw evol ni yletarepsed
.taorht s’xof eht rof og ot tuoba hguoht sa seye reh deworran enimsaJ
.dlog ni thgiew sih htrow saw hcet murd doog yllaer a ,sediseB
,teef reh ta kcapkcab eht fo tuo aremac reh gnitteg tuoba thguoht annA
”?gnihtemos uoy ksa I naC .kcaJ ,yeH“
”.uoy fo lla ot klat ot stnaw ohw yaw eht no retroper a tog ev’ew srehto eht dnimeR“ ,dias tsuj
.srae sih ot tes tnediffid a htiw puorg eht dehcaorppa
.esion htiw eunev eht llif dna
.hgis a ylerab htiw swen eht koot enimsaJ
,emoh tuoba gnikniht fo daetsnI
.thgin looc ,dlim a otni denrut dah yad toh ehT
,elims t’ndid eH
,dewollof ettolrahC
etorw dna tuo ”htiaf“ dekram ehs
.flesreh ot lla sruoh wef a detnaw tsuj ehS .dehgis annA
.snaicisum dna seidaor eht gnoma tluser a sa tuo doots dna tius kcalb taen a gniraew saw eH
.enohp reh no aremac eht gninepo tsuj tuoba thguoht
.tem ylbaborp d’yeht ,haeY
gnitiaw fo sruoh lareves tnaem hcihw ,thgie litnu no og t’ndid dnab reh tuB
daeha nar sthguoht s’annA
esop yrgna na kcurts enimsaJ ”!tluaf s’yhcrairtap eht s’tI“
”.won thgir asluT ni erew ew thguoht I ,hO“
,doof gnikooc ot tsuahxe kcurt morf
.tsael ta ,reweivretni doog a saw god ehT
”?ecnatsid gniklaW ?nivaG ,letoh ruo si raf woH“
eman reh dengis ehS
egattoc moordeb-owt reH
.reh rof ti kcolnu ot ni deirruh tac ybbat regnig a semit wef a ti ta delttar annA retfa tub
.swap htob ni ladep eht gnidloh saw kcaJ
.tuo saw egnuol raer eht ni CA eht ,esrow sgniht ekam ot dna
,dnopser dluoc god eht erofeB
.sub eht no gnipeels fo daetsni thginot letoh a ni erew yeht denoitnem ehs nehw krims s’nrohgnorp eht derebmemer dna ,tey tem d’yeht fi derednow annA
.nommoc erew setoyoc erehw tsew tuo erew yeht sselnu
”,uoy teem ot desaelP“
nrow erew revoc eht fo segde ehT
.snossel murd gnikat detrats I nosaer eht erew uoY“
.llew meht hsiw ot emac ohw sregnarts fo edarap a—
,rednels eht dah ehS .dias lrig eht
.esae noisnet reh tlef ehs ,deklaw ehs sA
swalc reh htiw ruf yffulf reh dekar ehS
.naf 1# ym
.ybraen tlah a ot delbmuts noil niatnuom gnuoy a
.letoh eht ot klaw reh deunitnoc annA
.dias eh ”,tpurretni ot yrroS“ ”?pu s’tahW“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.oot rehtegot swap reh detsiwt yzzI
.ecnalg yrosruc a naht erom annA evag meht fo rehtieN
”.yad gnol a neeb s’tI
.retnab lausu ’setamdnab reh rof yadot ecneitap on dah ehs dnuof annA
,seitseb erew annA dna ehs yliranidrO
,ruf reh gnixif dna raew ot tahw gnidiced yad lla tneps ylbaborp dah god roop ehT
.sgniw eht otni mih dewollof annA
?thgin tsal wohs ruo fo weiver eht ees uoy did ,zzaJ ,doG ym hO“ ,dias eivE
.gniruot tiuq uoy retfa hcet murd a emoceb ot dediced uoy yhw wonk ot tnaw I sseug I—
.efil reh fo yad tseb eht gnivah ylraelc saw ohw ,retsacdop dnolb eht htiw gnitrilf nivaG dnuof ehS
,god fo dnik emos ro flow yffurcs a rof nekatsim saw ehs emit eht flaH
stsoh dna wahS .C.K sa noitcif ysatnaf dna yrruf htob setirw ohw
,ni gnikcehc swerc thgil dna dnuos eht fo srebmem erew emos
.tohsrae fo tuo erew yeht sa noos sa dias ehs ”,kcaJ
.wahS etaK sa tsacdoP slaminA egnartS
.ytimynona ni ettal lemarac a pis
deyevnoc depoh ehs taht evaw daorb dna elims a reweivretni eht evag ehS
.dlrow eht ssorca seunev derdnuh a fo thguoht ehs ,daetsnI
”kcehC dnuoS“ saw sihT
.noonretfa eht fo tser eht rof roivaheb tseb rieht no dna elbatneserp eb ot dedeen lla yeht
.sliart gnikih htiw aera dedoow a ot pu dekcab
,gnimmurd sih tuoba hcum klat t’ndid kcaJ
.reh drawot gninnur spetstoof thgil fo dnuos eht ta dehctiwt srae reH
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sserP nosinnaM morf elbaliava
.lufthguoht dekool kcaJ
.asluT ni eb yllaer thgim yehT
”.naf gib a si retsacdop eht enimsaJ lleT
”,thginot letoh a
”.sknaht ,tuo meht yrt ll’eW“
.lrans a ni hteet reh morf kcab dellup spil dna denettalf srae ,denrut ehS
,slewot on era ereht fi dna enog s’retsacdop eht sa noos sa gnirewohs m’I tub ,eniF“
.xis ta ,retal si oidaR .retsacdop lacoL“
”.peels hguone teg ot deirt ,hcum oot ytrap ot ton deirt I .yllaer ,od nac uoy lla s’tahT
.tevlev hguor ekil ruf kcalb htiw raeb etitep a
.dehgual noil niatnuom ehT
”.thginot hguorht su teg ll’taht
.elims a htiw dias annA
.daor eht no detardyhed teg ot ysae saw tI
”.traehteews ,htiaf eht peeK
.dias eh ”,kool resolc a koot I os reilrae ffo tlef gnihtemos thguoht I“
”,eciohc dooG“ .gniK deepS eht no delttes dna sladep htob deirt ehS
.dilos derob saw I !on on on on oN“
,ti deppord evah tsum enoemos ;taht enod dah ehs yaw oN
.tseretni htiw dekcirp srae s’annA
.eno tsal reh saw siht ebyaM
”.evirra ew nehw gnitiaw ladep tnemecalper a tog ev’ew erus ekam dna gninrom worromot asluT ot daeha llac ll’I .ereh tes lla er’ew kniht I
.ot gninaem reh tuohtiw gaw a evag liat s’annA .delkcuhc kcaJ
.ti yojne yllaer I
.ylduol erom neve dewehc dna htuom reh otni eci fo knuhc rehtona deppop eivE ,rewsna nI
”?ladep kcik eht htiw gnorw gnihtemoS
,ladep tneced a evah yeht fI .raeg esuoh eht hguorht kool ot enog s’retomorp ehT“
.thguoht annA ,etal os tuo eb ot gnuoy oot ylerus—reganeet a fo ecnaraeppa deggel-gnol
”,tluaf ym lla s’tI“
.das elttil a dna dnik saw
.lla ti dniheb niar gnidnepmi fo tnecs yllihc eht htiw
.enola eb ot detnaw tsuj ehS
.edutilos lufssilb ni ruoh na dneps dna pohs eeffoc a dnif ot emit evah t’ndluow
.eciov yrgna ,talf a ni dias enimsaJ
.regnif dewalc-ybbuts a htiw detniop eH ”.ereH“
,hguoht ,gnol erofeB
yadot tub ,loohcs hgih ecnis sdneirf
,ruf reh gniyrd-wolb yllacitnarf saw dna derewohs ydaerla dah ettolrahC
.eromyna reh yamsid t’ndid thguoht ehT
boj eht fo trap saw ti tuB
,yeH“ .raeg reh htiw eussi tnatropmi yllaer a rof tuo kcud ot dah ehs taht terger
”.yako smees tI ?rof gnikool I ma tahW“ .ti ta denworf ehS
yawa deniard noonretfa eht rof snalp s’annA
.murd ssab eht ot sladep eht fo eno hcatta ot ylffits tlenk kcaJ
”.smurd gniyalp detrats uoy yhw tegrof reveN“
.weksa raeppa did ti ta dekool ehs taht won hcihw
,knird a htiw gnixaler fo daetsni taht swen eht erahs ot tfel annA
”.giwduL dekil syawla ev’I
.tnemeticxe erup fo tnemom a dah ehs
”?gnihtemos ro s’mom ruoy siht saW“
.dlofnu ot srae reh dna elttes ot selkcah reh decrof annA
.tpurretni ot detah annA
.ytip otni dedaf tnemtneser s’annA
.yltneiciffe sreward hsac eht detnuoc dnuohyerg a elihw rab eht nwod gnipiw saw nooccar A
?nivaG ,thgiR“ .reganam rieht ta dekool ehS
tekcop sih ni delbmuf eH
,mih ediseb doots god dnolb A
”.eromyna hguone s’ti erus ton m’I dna—em rof ti htrow gniruot sekam taht gniht ylno eht s’tI“ .deksa annA
.moor ruoy ni egagguL .sruoy s’ereH“
retal setunim eviF
.lautir wohs-tsop lausu rieht saw tI
,gnilims llits ,nehT
.soahc potsnon saw trecnoc llams a neve ta egatskcaB