gniworg ,wodniw ym fo tnorf ni detaolf dna ,enim fo ezis eht eciwt tuoba saw pihs ehT
,lennahc eht nepo kcilf I
,"ffo dellac saw ytnuob ehT ?raeh uoy t'ndiD"
"?retupmoC" dias dna
.ereh gnikniht teg s'tel ,yakO
,seinapmoc elpitlum rof retirw GPR potelbat a si ohw
...d'I leuf eht llA
.dekrow reven s'ti ,yakO ...naht
,sruo fo esrevinu 'lo gib siht ni sgniht doog
.dah I eciohc ylno eht saw ti yllautcA
.doog gnikool t'nsaw siht ,ti nmaD
,won thgiR .emit rehtona rof yrots eht evas ll'I ,llew hO
"?ris ,taht htiw seirf tnaw uoY
.hteet eht ot demra era syug esehT
.ti eveileb etiuq t'ndluoc em fo traP
.thgiferif a ni meht tsniaga ecnahc on m'I
pot eht dna ,yako saw eeffoc fo puc yM
.erehwemos ereh eb ot dah tI .yletarepsed dnuora delbmarcs dna
.ereh morf thgilf sruoh ytriht tuoba gnittis si ,tnemom eht ta otni teg ot tnaw t'nod yllaer I taht stneve fo seires a hguorht ,dnA
,teiuq dna lufecaep ,ecin
.pu tuhs hO .ti s'taht ,haeY
.ffuts lufesu ,wonk'y ,thgif nug a gnivivrus ekil sgniht gninrael ysub oot saw I
meht evag yeht ,daetsnI
;egassem noissimsnart gnimocni na saw tI
.tfel evah I leuf fo setunim eerht lla htiW
.tsom eht gnidaerd saw I trap eht saw siht dnA
?em no nosaes gnitnuh nepo ,ti si tahW
elohw eht ,detnevni erew yeht ecniS
,dennirg I   .deksa eh
.yllanif ksa I "?tnaw uoy od tahw ,thgirlA"
?tinni ,emoh s'ti dnA
.desselb m'I ebyaM
- eeffoc emos knard I .xaler ot
.yug gnitsurt laer a er'uoY"
,si gniht eht ,eeS
dediced dna pu swaptoof ym tup I
.mih tsol d'I thguoht d'I !parC
.cihc yreV .gniht gib eht erew yeht ,elihw a roF
"?retupmoc ym ot od uoy did tahW" .yob-tar saw tI
.ekahs ot trats sgniht
.klat ot stnaw eh ,taerG
,em fo tnorf ni lenap eht nO
sti fo emos nees evah d'I ,rehtruf dnuora kool ot daeh ym denrut dah I fI
.neppah dluoc gnihtyna ,tniop taht morF .ti fo lortnoc gnikat dna ,enim htiw gnitcennoc retupmoc sih devlovni ti ,yllacisaB
"?uoy dluoc ,tfil a em evig nac uoy esoppus t'noD"
.snonnac sih htiw esool stel em dniheb krej-tar eht ,tnemom taht ta dnA
.dioretsa taht no ereht gnittis tsuj saw leuf ehT"
t'nseod ria eht erus ekam dna ,ylppus leuf eht eganam ,sesruoc tolp ,etagivan ot yllacisab si boj s tI
.won krow lliw erofeb morf yolp ym kniht t'nod I ,nosaer emos roF
".ti gnisu saw ydoboN
.elbanosaer eb ot gnilliw saw eh ,yltnerappa oS
"rednerrus ot sdnoces evlewt evah uoY"
.gnitaeh fo dnik emos htiw ti tif ot elba eb neve thgim I
gnihtemos htiw retupmoc a etaerc ot aedi doog a eb dluow ti thguoht ozob emos ,oga sraey ytnewt tuobA .raeppasid
,setag eseht pu edam snoitaroproc gib esoht fo eno ,oga sraey derdnuh a tuobA
htiw od ot gnihtemoS .enilef-flah lla er'eW .sinaryK morf m'I
.em morf setunim evif tuoba etag pmuj a saw erehT !tnellecxE
.retupmoc sih otni edoc eht depyt dneirf tar elttil yM
.esoppus I ,laed taerg a yllaer toN
.yaw eht ni teg tsuj yehT"
.pan ym gniyojne saw I ,yllaer emahS
rorrim tekcop ytsurt ym tuo llup I ,spihcorcim dna sdraob tiucric fo elip sselesu taht morf gninihw eht tuo gninuT     .'sselesU
,seenk dna sdnah ym no nwod tog I
.retipuJ ,ecalp ynnuF
.em dniheb tuhs demmals etag eht ,neht dnA
.tnadnuder emoceb hcum ytterp sah gniht etag pmuj
.lluh s'pihs eht deraor ,hceercS
,dias eciov-tar eht
.ti diova ot yaw on saw ereht tuB
.seye ym denepo I
.llaweriF eht dna em neewteb ,wodniw eht ni gnignah llits saw pihs sih ,hguone eruS
,devlovni yllacisab hcihW .'retcarahC'
.eivetS ot gniklat elihw taht od ot detnaw ev'I semit fo ytnelp s'ereht
.erif hctac ot pihs eht fo kcab eht gnitcepxe flah saw I ,tnemom taht tA   !parC
?trapa gnillaf dna ytsurc ,dlo si pihs elttil siht noitnem I diD
".owt ruof thgie ,enin xis neves s'edoc ehT"
.niaga ecaps laer ni kcab er'ew dna ,tlah a ot dnirg yeht
.egapbew rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,pu swaptoof ym tup ,riahc eht ni kcab xaler I
,ereht dneirf yttar ym delworg
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.seivom eht t'nia sihT !esael-huP
.naht separcs erom fo tuo em tog s'enil tahT
,niaga nottub lennahc eht sserp I
.emoh llac I tahw si dna
.ocsid a ni erif ekil maws xulfni cimsoc fo sthgil gnizalb eht ,pihs eht dnuorA
rof gniog gniht siht peek ot elba neeb evah dluow ...deworrob
.enim ot klat naht rehtar flesti dellik dah retupmoc s'ymene yM
.taht ekil seicrem llams rof ssendoog knahT
.stej eht ot rewop lla tcerid ot
.tsal ym eb thgim ti gnikniht
!sepyt suoirafen esoht fo eno ton m'I ,oN
.doog yrev hsilgnE kaeps on I"
,yakO   .setag pmuj ydoolB .thgir ,haeY
.nwo ruoy esu ot refas hcum er'uoy
.delworg dna ,em ta thgir dekool eH
.enim tpecxe ,haey hO
.em ta thgir gnitniop erew sterrut nug gib ydoolb sti taht si rettam seod tahW
a ees dluoc I ,yks thgin delkceps tsav eht gnoma ,ecnatsid eht nI
.ekoms eht llems dluoc I ,erif no erew lluh renni eht fo straP
.hteet ym gnittirg ,tcapmi resal rof decarb I
.ihcatiH roirraw ecaps evarb ,elbon eht rof dne gnittif a toN
.esrevinu eht fo elpoep eht tsniaga semirc rof detnaW"
.ytilanosrep a gnilbmeser
.nettogrof d'I esac ni
,hteet tcefrep
.tnelis seog dna ,elbigilletni-flah gnihtemos srettuts retupmoc ehT .lenap eht revo
.enihw gniraor a evag dna
.oot taht esol d'I os ,pihs eht otni detargetni saw ti ,haey ho ,dnA
.ereht teg ot elba eb d'I ,ebyam tsuj ,ebyaM
.rettam t'nseod ezis taht yas yeht ,llew hO
.slennut etag pmuj eht edisni etagivan yllautca t'nac knuj fo knuh siht esuaceb yllaicepse
ni dekcik stej ehT
.snirg nam-tar ehT
.ti dnuof sregnif yM
.tar a ekil dekool nevE .sreksihw dna ,seye ydaeb llams ,eson gnol a dah eH
,retipuJ fo bro delriws-der egral
.lufesu syawla era dna
.mih ta eeffoc fo spuc worht syawla dluoc I ,esrow ot semoc esrow fi dnA
.gnihton naht retteb s'ti ,yeH
.sgniht eseht tuoba tib elttil a
,taes ym hguorht pu thgir seohce taht gnilbmur
"?leasrey ti ead on ey nac ,hattam eht s'tuhW" .ti dlot I "llaweriF eht rof esruoc a teS"
”eibmoz eganeet yag a saw I“ fo rohtua dna
".yug gnorw eht tog ev'uoy ,dub yrroS"
.tohs a htrow saw tI .nmaD ".oot
.gniciton enoyna tuohtiw srats fo aes a ni gnitaolf ereh tis tsuj ylisae nac dna
.ereht yenom ruoy rof laed doog a teg ot redrah gnitteg s'tI
.ereht tuo ecin s'weiv eht tsael ta ,llew hO
,tnemom taht ta gnittih saw I hcihw ,deeps lluf tA
eeffoc ym fo sniamer tahw kconk dna
.gniht enilef a s'ti ,yeH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ebyC nosilA yb
.krej etelpmoc a ton s'eh tsael ta lleW
.syug esoht ebyam tpecxE
.noivilbo ni dednepsus gnignah
.did ti ,hguone erus dnA
?retteb gnihtyna fo thguoht evah dluoc uoy kniht uoy ,tahW
.dedolpxe senigne eht erofeb rewop eht ffo demmals dna ,feiler fo hgis a dehtaerb I
.edoc eht gniretne dehsinif eH
.yas ot gnihtemos fo kniht ot deirt I
"?habbod eew 'nignim ay ,oon tnaw ay ead tiW" .gnilwocs ,sraeppa ecaf nooccar dezitigid a ,wodniw eht fo thgir eht ot dna evoba rotinom a nO
,wolfni hsac suoires emos ro ,pihs retteb a dah I fI
ti yas I .rohpatem a si taht ,sey dnA
".ekatsim gib a lla saw ti tuo snruT" ,yrt I
?ti si ,yad doog yrev a eb ot tuo gninrut ton yllaer s'tI .ton sseuG
?od uoy gnihtyreve ta tseb ruoy yrt ot uoy llet reve rehtom ruoy t'ndiD
.'rennacs' delebal eno eht ,thgir ym ot lenap eht dekcehc I
.nosaer emos rof siht ekil semit ta od ot dnet yeht sa ,lenap eht morf pu tohs skraps wef a dna
.gniknird rof retaw eht lla deen I ;wol gninnur neeb evah seilppus ,yeH
.yleruces denetsaf llits saw
,ria dloc taht fo htaerb peed a thguac I tnemom a roF
.snonnac resal htiw timreh citohcysp a htiw gnilaed saw I ,taerg hO ".yaw
,llaweriF eht fo syab egarots eht ni gnittis saw leuf eht tuB .sedaced
.snoom fo yarra eguh
.reggib dna reggib
.mih gninnurtuo tuoba thguoht I
,edecnoc I "enif ,eniF"
nottub eht maj I dna ,pihs ym otni delemmup nonnac resal fo yellov rehtonA
.seinoloc narret eht tis ,elbaecitonnu ,ecafrus sti no nwoD
.ti saw taht ,eciov ekil-tar a draeh d'I reve fI
sserP straeH peeD yb
,tnecca ranul tseb ym ni rekaeps eciov eht otni llac I ,"yrros I"
.od spihs lla sa ,retupmoc a htiw emac ti ,pihs siht thguob I nehW   .deksa ti
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.rotinom ym revo eciov eht
.woh denrael reven I esuaceb ,tsenoh saw hcihW .derewsna I ".t'nac I
.ti ot txen lebal a depat d'I esuaceb taht wenk I
tsuj nevE !nmad ,naem I
"evila ni uoy ekat ll'I dna ,retupmoc ruoy ot ssecca revo nruT"
,pihs ym fo tipkcoc eht ni ereh gnittis
.dehsarc dna tibro sti tsol ...mre
!suoixonbo taht yllautca s'eH
.lenap lortnoc sih no sthgiL
"!ihcatiH"   .ti desserp I
.dloc llits s'ti dna gnihtolc lamreht fo sreyal eerht gniraew m'I
.kaerb a emmiG ?semirc dnA
.krej-tar eht dias
”ihcatiH roirraW ecapS“ saw sihT
.fo erac ekat ot tnatropmi erom hcum gnihtemos saw ereht ,lla fo tsrif tuB
.taht rof leuf hguone ton ,haey hO
.deksa I "?deneppah tahW"
.esruoc fo ,ytnuob ruoY"
.hgis detaefed a evag eh dna ,rotinom ym no llits saw ecaf deson-detniop s'krej-taR
.sdnoces ytnewt tuoba ni latem parcs otni pihs eritne siht nrut dluoc taht snonnac htiw ,em gnisahc reggub eguh siht htiW
,eeffoc ym dna em tsuJ
derettuts "?lleh eht tahW"   ...litnU
,eivetS oN"   .denihw ti
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
".mucs etarip luof ,won uoy tog ev'eW" ,dennirg eH
.etarip a flesym llac ton yletinifed d'I tub ,etarucca yltcaxe t'nsaw gniht roirraw eht ebyam ,yakO ".esrevinu
"!haggeb yknits ay 'nikeer erup rey ,rewohs a atni leasrey tig nA"   .tcefrep m'I ,nmaD
,rekaeps eht revo nam-tar eht sdnimer
.tsaf oot nrut I nehw taht seod tI
”ihcatiH roirraW ecapS“
"ihcatiH etariP ecapS"   "?siht s'ohW"
.sdad-ood cinortcele esoht fo eno evah spihs tsom ,haey tuB
,slennut etag denodnaba dlo eht ni tuo edih ot
".dellirht era sdneirf ruoy teb I .toN
.etag pmuj a gnideen tuohtiw etag a snepo dna ,pihs ruoy fo mottob eht otno skcits taht dad-ood cinortcele elttil a si hcihw ,ygniht rotarelecca etag a sah esrevinu eht ni pihs yreve tuoba tsuj taht si smelborp elttil eht fo eno ,woN ?eeS
a dna redduhs tnarbiv a htiW
.yob tnedor dennirg
.swols pihs eht sa
.won enif saw gnihtyreve tub ,thgiferif eht ni noitats lortnoc eht rednu dellor dah tI
...evah dluoc dioretsa eht ,leuf taht lla devom t'ndah enoemos fi ,naem I
,naem I .nwod flesti tuhs dna ,dedaolrevo evah tsum metsys retupmoc s'ecaf-taR !esruoc fO
.enim saw taht ,lleW
.ecaps lamron otni kcab pord ot ydaer er'ew dna flesti riaper ot deganam s'retupmoc eht ,retal sruoh eviF
.meht fo eno si eeffoc dna
.noitcelfer ym kcehc dna
,pihs gib a t'nsi sihT
sruoloc dairym htiw yllaudarg gnislup ,wols ot strats edistuo srats fo mrotserif eht ylwolS
,ekahs ot detrats sgnihT
.sah ti 'retcarahc' retteb eht ,retupmoc ruoy rof yap ot gnilliw er'uoy yenom erom eht ,retal sraey ytnewt ,si gniht ynnuF .siht ,llew
.enil waj enilucsam gnorts dna
...aporuE no kcab ,emit a fo em sdnimer taht ,tcaf nI
.tuohs I "!uoy dniheb kooL"
.eciohc rehto yna saw ereht ekil kool t'ndiD
.ecivres a gnidivorp saw I
.roirraw ecaps elbon ,evarb ehT
.dah I naht erom em tsoc dluow metsys retupmoc wen A
.pihs s'krej-tar eht stis
,sdlareme neerg tnarbiv fo ruoloc eht seyE
,yllaer elttuhs a fo erom
.eivetS fo ecaf detalixip eht ot pu dekool I   "?od uoy did tahW
.dellips saw pord a toN
".uoy eveileb t'nod I"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sey ,elttuhs ograc llams eW
.rotinom eht no pu spop ecaf sih dna ,nottub eht tih I
,ebyC nosilA    ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
.elttil a tsuj ecneconni ym gnitareggaxe saw I ebyam os ,yakO
,nmad tuB .oga seirutnec wef a yug tsitneics emos yb stnemirepxe citeneg
.aedi eht teg uoy ,gnissim gniog negyxo ,tcurtsed-fleS
.emoh kcab esruoc ym rof nottub eht tih dna ,eeffoc ym deppis
emos era ereht ,yllufknahT
"!leasti dellik 'na 'new gnaht lutnem eew ahT"
.esu ot enim fo niarb tnecifingam taht tup s'tel ,oS
.mih tramstuo ot emiT
,gnitaeh eht gniriwer yllautca dna dehsiugnitxe serif eht gnitteg retfa ,oS
* * *   .uoy dnim ,emit erofeb toN
.esnes tcefrep edam lla ti neht dnA
.hguor elttil a gnikool m'I os
.oot tuo skcehc nrettap eciov ruoy dnA"
.dediced I ,taht fo erac ekat ot deen d'I
lenap eht ffo sllor ,dehcatta llits pot ,eeffoc fo puc yM
.hcum yrev yap ot gnilliw t'nsaw I dnA
,otsilaC taen ,thgir eht oT
.evah dluow ereht tuo yug rehto emos ,ti ekat t'ndid I fi ,yeH
?tinni ,dnuos gnirussaeR
.ereh tuo dloc erus s'ti ,puY
?em esirprus ton taht seod yhW ".esruoc
.roolf eht ssorca srettiks dna
,mih dlot I ",kooL"
.kaerb a evah reven nac em ekil syug tneconni
llits saw eH   .yddub tnedor elttil ruo dewohs llits hcihw rotinom eht otni dekool I ?emoh ydobon saW .ffo erew strop sti ni sthgil eht ,won tuB
.diputs eb dluow taht esuaceb ,ytilanosrep a evah yllautca t'ndluoc sretupmoc ,esruoc fO
.seye ym tuhS
.emoh ti ekam reven d'I ,htiw revo ti tog I sselnU
"...esaelp esaelp esaelp esaelP" ,flesym ot derepsihw I ",esaelP"
?tnagele erom gnihtemos gnitcepxe erew uoy ,tahW
.tcatni saw ti ,sey dnA
diuqil gnimaets ,mraw eht fo pis a ekat I
.ykaeuqs ylthgils dna ylkcarc ,eciov eht emac
?tahw ro thgir sseug ym saw ,yoB
.elohmrow laicifitra
.ta drows resal a ekahs nac uoy naht separcs erom fo tuo yaw ym kniht ot elba neeb ev'I tub ,gnihtyna ro garb ot tnaw t'nod I woN
niffE' ro ,taht rehtie saw tI .eivetS dellac s'retupmoc eht dna ,sey hO
"!derots syawla s'leuf erehw s'tahT"
.ecaps dnuora poh ot uoy gniwolla
,tnecsenimul a otni gniremmihs thgil fo srats gnivaeh taerg
.txen neppah dluow tahw ot drawrof gnikool t'nsaw I
”ihcatiH roirraW ecapS“:yojne esaelP
.kcirt tseb ym esu ot emit
.saedi fo tuo m'I ,yakO
?noitnem I t'ndid ,hO
,"noitats toped a saw dioretsa tahT"
.retteb yltnatsni leef dna
.egassem gnimmocnI
.ihcatiH .yaw eht yb eman ym s'taht ,haey hO
.gnitlusni eb ot deen on s'ereht ,wonk'Y
",sdrocer ecilop eht sehctam DI pihs ruoY"
eltsac gnitaolf citsejam ,tnaillirb ehT .llaweriF eht si
si yrots s’yadot dna
.ecaps lamron otni tuo kcab pord uoy devirra ev'uoy nehw dna ,dnuora frus ,etag eht otni no hsur uoY
.stej eht rof nottub eht tih I
,melborp a eb dluoc ereht gnitteG
,ycarip no sdrocer ecilop ot ssecca latot evah niarb a flah htiw yranecrem doog-on yreve tel yeht ecnis reve ,wonk'Y
.ihcatiH ,roirraw ecaps suoiciv eht fo
,thgirlA   .eivetS depley
"!sdnoces owT" ?huh ,yssalC
.reverof no hcterts ot demees emit dnA
yna sa emit a tseb sa saw won taht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.htaerb ym dleh I
"sdnoces thgiE"   ?deifsitaS
.no deknilb thgil eulb elttil a
.sgel ym neewteb liat ym htiw ,retnuh ytnuob tar deciov ykaeuqs a morf yawa gninnuR
,nepo maws etag pmuj eht sa lluh ym otni dednuop egrahcsid nonnac resal fo yellov lanif A   .ereht tsomlA
.adamra eritne na eb llew sa thgim yeht ,ereh pihselttab-a-rof-esucxe yrros ym ot derapmoc tub ,demra ylthgil yrev er'yeht ,yllautcA
.ees'y ,gnixif deen syawlA
,elttuhs elttil siht fo ezis eht semit neves tuoba s'tI .pihs niam ym
,ecirp tneced a hctac nac sretupmoc
.ton ebyam ,oN ...mih thgiftuo dluoc I ebyaM
.enoyna yb debrutsidnu
.tuort ladicius a ekil lluh s'pihs ym otni mals yehT
.orf dna ot gniyaws ,gnilkcub tnes saw pihs ehT .ereht os ,si
?rof taht ekil em ta gnikool uoy era tahw ,yeH .krow t'nseod tI
,yob tar detroter ,"meht fo yna evah t'noD"
,eciov eht decnuonna
.em fo daeha demool etag pmuj ehT
,em dna ti neewteb taht tpecxE
.syad retteb nees s'ti os ,yakO
.tuo erew sthgil eht tub ,ereht
.stej orter eht no tih dna
.su tnes setag pmuj eseht saw ti reverehw fo tuo deppord ew litnu tiaw ot dediced dna - mraw llits
.uoy llet em tel ,ytterp era erus sgniht nmaD
!daed s'retupmoc yM"
sepyt suoirafen rehto dna setarip ,skoorc ,srelggums rof ycnednet eht fo esuaceb ,tcaf nI
!tsenoh ,doog llits s'ti tuB .semit wef a egabrag sa yawa deluah gnieb ti pots ot dah ev'I
.retupmoc eht derewsna
.thgir eht ot smaj eson sti dna ,slortnoc eht no knay I
taes tolip eht otni kcab teg I
.gnihtemos ot no yllaer saw 'ecaps fo muucav dloc' eht tuoba gniht taht dias tsrif reveohw ,wonk'Y   ebyC nosilA yb
?tahw ro doog kool I od
,htaerb peed a koot I oS