hkrrL dnefed ot hsiw ylurt uoy fi tub
.sneila eht rof thgif ot su fo lla tfel ,reh tfel uoY
.elzzum ym delknirw I
?yeht era erehw dna sruoy sdnammoc htgnerts esohW
.llaf elzzum ym dna xaler sredluohs ym tel I
">.regral eloh eht ekam uoy erofeb won og ,arruW ,esaelP
.gnorw gnihtemos enod dah I retfa
.uoy no tiaw ot gniw' ym ot kcab em dehcram yeht nehT .uoy llac ll'ew
">.hsilgnE skaeps uoy fo eno sselnu ,etalsnart ot evah lliw I
.os ro ruoh tsrif eht retfa yrgna erom dna
.su htiw eb ot detnaw I ...I"
?esae ta em tup ot tca na tsuj
.enola erew ew sa noos sa ni detrats I
">?tuo dneirf namuh ym tel ot meht teg uoy naC
.ti ot mhtyhr gnitaludnu na s'erehT
.s'ecuaStoH ot zzub a dnes ot pmocinim ym desu I erofeb
,kciuq erusaem rieht teg ot deirt I
,sesnefed latibro dliub ot ygolonhcet rieht esu dluoc eW
.sseltniop eb dluow gnithgiF
.krowtra epor-nevow dna
evah yehT .tfel yehT .emac yehT<"
.srerednaw fo lufdnah a saw tsol dah ew lla thguoht ew tsrif tA
.scisab eht tog I tub uoy sa llew sa kaeps t'ndid ehs yawynA !oohW
.sraey ym fo 21 naht erom ni
.don a htiw elttob eht detpecca dna drawrof deklaw I
,hkrrL no degnahc dah revetahw etipseD
.demra erew yeht dnA
.su dniheb seno eht fo eno dias
2 fo 2 traP ,yrraH yb
pil sih delruc redael ehT
.denrut dna detrons eh dna
,su llac t'noD .yawa yats ot sredael ym llet ,tibro ni ro tenalp no emoclew toN
.seye eht ni mih dekool dna desuap I
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
,rood eht ta kool ot denrut I nehT
ksed eht fo edis sih no rood a denepo eH
?sknaht dna esiarp rof gnikool emac uoy oS<"
,eenk ot redluohs morf spirts dessorc
,em sdnimer taht ,yeh ,hoO
em no kcab sih denrut redael ehT
.rehtie tis ton did dna
devrac etanro eht koot dna ,deddon I
gniteerg ym ot esnopser ni sdnah sih esiar ot detrats ruof eht fo enO
,sdnah sih desiar eH
,seman tnereffid wef a rednu sehsilbup dna setirw ohw ,yrraH yb
.nalc on yltnerappa saw ereht taht won saw ti revetahw rO
">.htap worran a gniklaw era eW .og tsum uoy
">.deniamer eloh eht tuB
?nu'hkrrL rehto fo trofmoc on htiw
.eye eht werd ti taht ecalp fo tuo os dekool tub ,flesti yb yranidro ytterp ,ksed nedoow a saw elddim eht nI .ytpme
">?sey ,emit gnol a ni tsrif ruoY
?niaga reh erujni dluow uoY?rehtom ym dnA<"
".gnoleb I erehw ,dnik nwo ym htiw eb oT
.ygrene fo etsaW .sddo daB .rood
">.dessimsid er'uoy ,uoy knahT<"
.decap dna ,moor eht ni erutinruf ylno eht saw hcihw hcneb eht morf niaga pu tog I oS
nwod tes I dna ecuaStoH oS
,rehtegot hteet ym dekcilc I
.em fo erew yeht naht mih fo suoicipsus erom eb tsum yeht os
.did ew nehw su dniheb ni llef neht dna
,em ot dias tnorf ni eno ehT
.neila gnihtemos otni
.lluf-flah llits ,nwod puc eht tes I
.lennahc mmoc etavirp ruo revo ecuaStoH dias
".ydaer er'uoy litnu em llet ot evah t'nod uoy tub ,uoy ot dias yeht tahw ksa d'I
".mih htiw eltneg eb oS .ylisae sesiurb eh dnA
.yltnecer litnu t'ndid rO
?dlrow eritne siht fo ekas eht rof enod dah I tahw wonk eh t'ndiD
.moor eht fo tuo teg ot lufetarg ,dewollof I
.thguondaerd tlatseG eht no tluassa eht ni welf I
.hguorht del neeb dah I rood eht fo noitcerid eht ni derutseg I ">...siht neht dnA
.neht ,krow retfa ebyaM<"
,reh rof dna ,uoy rof tseb eb dluow ti kniht I<" .daeh sih koohs eH
,dias I ",emas ,haeY"
">.hsifles eb ton oD
.sraey eht etipsed ,yletaidemmi mih wenk I .elcnu ym saw
dnoces eht saw sihT
.nedrag ruo fo llaw eht ni eloh a erot yeht ,emac ecnaillA eht nehW .arruW ,oN<"
">,od yeht taht erus ma I<"
,yas ot deganam I ",haeY"
">.smret ruo no tub ,ecnaillA eht nioj ylurt lliw ew yademoS
.em ot klat dna ereh ni emoc uoy fo eno tsael ta ,syug ,no emoC<"
.ecalp tsrif eht ni og ot ti detnaw dah I woh ediced ot gniyrt
.reddal ym fo esab eht ta em htiw dnats ot revo emac eh sa ecuaStoH dias ",syug eseht wonk uoy epoh I"
.gnicap deppots I .nepo gnuws ti
--dna ti wenk I taht wenk eh dna
,citonpyh tsomla saw thgis ehT
,rewsna t'ndid yehT
!aedi taerg a s'ti on oN"
.del htap eht erehw erus t'nsaw I taht tsaP
.mih rof saw tib tsal ehT
">.enog era dniheb tfel uoy hkrrL eht dna ,dniheb tfel uoy nalc eht esuaceB?yhW .enolA
">,tiderCrehtE ekat yeht sa gnol sa ,lleW
">?ool eht s'erehw ,gnirednow erew dna tenalp eht yb gnisiurc erew eW,syug yeH<"
--erofeb nees reven dah I mrofinu fo dnik emos gniraew lla erew yehT
.detcepxe fo tros I hcihw ,yawyna su gnitarapes pu dedne yehT   *****   .ecnelis ni
">?naem uoy od tahW<"
.sdraug eht htiw snoitasrevnoc dedis-eno detrats I
.em gnihctaw mih leef dluoc I
sciler cirotsih htiw detaroced llits saw tI
.em htiw knird a evah dna mlac eb
?rehtom ym si erehW
.sriats pu debmilc dna
.noitcaer rof srae ym dekrep I
ksed eht dniheb gnidnatS
.uoy fo yna naht retteb ecnaillA eht wonk I !pleh dluoc I
.deneppah dah tahw tuo dnif ot dedeen I tub
,ecalp tsrif eht ni ytic eht ni thgir dnal ot detnaw t'ndah I
">.meht nioj ot ydaer era ew fi niaga gniksa ,ecnis sraey wef yreve detisiv
.kihker fo elttob delaes na tuo koot dna
,nos-retsis ,esaelp oS
,emit tsaL  .yrruFoS no
.spoort dnuorg dah tlatseG eht ekil ton s'tI
.hguoht ,ti retnuoc ot lliw eht dekcal I
yrots s’yadoT dna
mra eno ni elttob eht deldarc I oS
.gninaem eht tog I tuB
.deksa eh "?won gnidaeh ew erehw oS"
.niaga evael ot em llet uoy teY<"
.ynapmoc dah eh tsael tA
.rehtruf mih htiw eugra ot detnaw I
,sregnif ym daerps dna sdnah ym desiar I oS
.meht no seye ym gnipeek
">?meht nioj ot uoy ecrof yeht diD ?hkrrL ot od yeht did tahW ?dnA<"
sllah eht deklaw ew sa seye ym desolc-flah I
eht edistuo tsuj erew klaw elttil ruo morf syug eht fo elpuoc a erus saw I hguoht
,ecafrus eht ta derats I
.ti dnatsrednu t'ndluoc ecuaStoH taht detnioppasid saw I dna krej a fo dnik gnieb saw I yawyna
.yawyna ti hsinif ,lleW
.russehK ronrevog won ,elcnu ym ta derats I
.dnatsrednu ot nageb I
,esruoc fo ,me' ot klat ot deirt I
foor lacinoc dereit sti
,kool gums a yug eno eht evig dna nrut ot detnaw I
.tluaf reh saw ti thguoht ehs kniht I
.klat ot elba eb llits thgim ew
">.elcnu ,smees ti sgniht fo tol a kniht uoY<" .deltsirb I
?tolip rethgif a sa mraedis a deen reve ew dluow yhw esuaceb ,demranu erew eW
.no gniog saw tahw gnirednow ereht gnidnats tsuj saw yug rooP
.taht odnu reven nac ew dna
knahT  .stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
llahnalC eht fo mottob eht sdrawot gnirats saw eH
.did ew tub ,woh erus ton llits m'I .now eW<" ,delworg I
,nosirp a ekil tliub t'nsaw moor ehT
">.feihc ,em rof mih gnihctef rof sknahT
.wonk I ,llew naem uoY
.eman ym meht dlot I nehw srae sih dekcirp dna daeh sih detlit meht fo eno taht deton I
.esruoc fo ,esnopser oN
*****   .gniwratS ym ot kcab em dael mih tel dna
?nepo llits snub taem esoht sekam taht skrow retaw eht raen ecalp taht si oS<"
.su htiw emoc htob lliw uoY<"
,detpmorp I ,eunitnoc ton did eh nehW
">.nu'hkrrL llits era uoy fi
">.em dlot yeht nehw kniht ot tahw wonk t'ndid I
wonk ot tnaw yllaer I tahw dnA
.ksed eht sdrawot kcab dedaeh eH
.trocse ym ta redluohs ym revo dekool eH
,gninnur ton tub gniyrruh erew yeht
,gnihtemos mih llet ot mih tnaw uoy fI<"
.desolc deniamer rood eht tuB
.taht fo trap saw I dnA
,arruW ,yrros ma I
.efas erew yeht erus ekam dna ylimaf ym dnif dluow I
">.arruW ,rehtie rebmemer I sa emas eht etiuq ton era uoY
">?reh ees em tel uoy t'now yhW
.ecanem elbicnivni taerg eht thgif ot yenruoj hsiloof ruoy no tfel uoY<"
llahnalC eht fo srood nedoow eguh eht ot yaw eht fo tser eht deklaw ew dna
.puc sih fo kcen tuops gnol eht morf knard neht ,dias eh
">?ebyam ,ereh tnemunom A
.enihw gniliart a htiw nwod gnirewop llits senigne ruo htiw
.emoclew s'oreh a detnaw dah yllaer I ebyaM
.sdlrow rehguor eht no deirrac secrof ytiruces namuh eht ekil
.gnisufnoc eb thgim ti woh ees nac I ,seY<"
.delkcuhc dna elzzum ym fo egdirb eht dehctarcs I
.taem dliw gnitnuh rof evah ot desu ew selfir elitcejorp eht htiw toN
">?evael ot deirt ew fi dneirf ym dna em toohs ot evah dluow yeht dias syug ruoy yhw em llet uoy nac woN<"
">.won revo s'ti tuB
.emit siht tsilkcehc thgilf-tsop eht htiw derehtob dah su fo rehtieN
sseltser em gnikam trats ot hguone wols tub ,gnissap saw tI
">.meht fo eno ni uoy eb dluow ti wonk ton dluoc I
eulb dna neerg fo lluf ,remmus ni enecs a fo larum detniap taerg ehT
,eurt kaepS ?kcab emoc yllaer uoy did yhW
.spihs ecnaillA ni gnivirra enoyna niated ot luruT-hkrrL eht morf sredro evah od ew tuB .citsaisuhtne
.desimorp eh ">,lliw uoY<"
.krow retfa htiw sknird gnivah saw I ohw sdraug eht yb deknalf
?ohw yb decroF ?hne ,decroF.uoy toohs ot decrof eb lliw ew spihs ecaps ruoy otni kcab teg ot yrt uoy fI
.sredle nalc eht rof rebmahc ecneidua fo dnik emos ecno saw kniht I hcihw
">.knird a uoy teg lliw I
.arruW ,taht dnatsrednu nac I<"
?enog saw I elihw ereh deneppah tahW ?taht si yhw dnA<"
">.nwo rieht fo stirips enif ynam evah snamuh eht tuB .sey ,kihker fO<" .dereffo eh puc nedoow
,sllaw eht tsniaga dehsup erew yehT
.urrliT fo nos ,arruW aklU m'I<"  .rebmemer I snalc ybraen eht fo yna ro ,aklU toN
.ytic eht ni sgnidliub dnuorg-evoba rehto eht evoba gnirewot
wollof ot su rof detiaw eerht rehto ehT
,nedrag regral hcum a fo trap won era eW
.sruoh rof moor taht ni em tpek yeht ,russehK<"
.taht dnuof I nehw thguoht I tahw enigami nac uoY .denodnabA .dloC
">.gnorts evil dna ,arruW ,siht ekaT<"
stnemurtsni tneicna
.yas ot desu srehcaet eht sa ,eert nellaf eht tsap
emit gnol a reh koot tI
,ereht saw em-toohs-ot-decroF .rM
.sutats sih gnikcerw tuohtiw toN .t'ndluoc eh tuB
'ronrevog' dias eh nehw tpecxE
".ecuaStoH ,sknahT"
?arruW ,uoy ees ot stnaw urrliT kniht uoy sekam tahW<"
.noitcurtsed desimorp eht deraps saw hkrrL fi lufetarg eb dluohs ew taht tub
,saw eh reveohw ,redael siht taht tuo tniop oT
.daeh sih koohs eH
.gnuts llits sdrow s'elcnu yM
”remmuS fo eM ot kaepS“
.yawa dekool dna deffurg eH
lirrahsekahs luQ q’rrruhg’L .gniteerg ni ,drawrof swalc
">.ssol ruoy tsap yaw reh dnif ot
neerg krad htiw staocgnol kcalB
detnuom-llaw eht ta dekooL .yawa dekool
,su ot tog yeht sa em ot txen pu derauqs eH
.'feihc' mih dellac I nehw seye sih deworran eH
snamuh eht gnoma enola tneps I sraey ehT ?tsol dna
.ecuas faelekar eht htiw
nirg yhtoot a mih evag I
.ecnaillA eht morf nruter ot tsrif eht ton era uoy tuB
.etsat eht yojne flesym tel dna mih denioj I
seirots sih fo tsom dnif nac uoy tub
">?tcilfnoc rieht rof etiteppa ruoy esol uoy diD
”remmuS fo eM ot kaepS“   yojne esaelP
.hkelreS nalc rO .akruS nalc rO
.seye eht ni elcnu ym dekool dna elzzum ym desiar I
.won noisserpxe gums eht htiw eno eht saw eH
.saw yllaer ti detinu woh derednow I snug htiw dnuora klaw ot dah yeht fi hguohT
">?taht si tahw dnA<"
?siht ekil em ot kaeps eh did yhW
”remmuS fo eM ot kaepS“
.egrahc ni enoemos ot su gnikat er'yeht emussa I .erus toN"
,dias eh sa ,sraey rof yna dah t'ndah I
.tis dna emoC .arruW ,nwod wolS<"
,gnol a ni eson sih fo tuo ti tel neht dna
.meht dniheb rood eht esolc meht draeh I litnu detiaw dna egru eht detsiser I tub
.kcab emac I taht raeh lliw ehS<"
"?thgir lla gnihtyrevE"
.yats ton dluoc I
htap eht gnikeeS
">.dniheb tfel uoy nalc eht niojer ot tnaw uoY
.su teem ot gnimoc noitpecer a saw erehT
.htgnerts rieht hctam tonnac eW
.oot em wenk eh dnA
.neht thgir denepo rood eht esuaceb meht nommus ot neesnu gnihtemos did russehK ro noitasrevnoc ruo ot gninetsil saw draug eht rehtiE
nees dah I tsrif ehT .lu'hkrrL ruoF
.no gniog saw tahw erus t'nsaw I sa
">?od ecnaillA eht did tahW ?eloh tahW<"
edam dah I sdneirf ehT
,kihker fo elttob a htiw flesmih deisub eH .tis t'ndid I
setunim net doog a rof ni em tup yeht moor elttil eht ni ecnelis ni tas I
,denialpxe dna detrons I
em elttar ot esoprup no ereht ni wets em edam yeht fi wonk t'ndid I
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
">.won uoy ot klat ot stnaw ronrevog ehT<" ,dias eH
.kihker sih fo erom deppis ,em dehctaw eH
?siht desuac ecnaillA eht daH
">?dneirf namuh ym tuoba tahW<"
.deffurg dna sdnah ym derewol I
.srehto fo sderdnuh htiw gnola ,dlrowemoh namuh eht no tnemunom a no devrac si eman yM
.regna fo og gnittel
.won uoy rof esu elttil sah ecnaillA eht dna
.gnitaelb ecnaillA eht fo hguonE<"
.em gnicarbme dna ksed eht dnuora gnimoc saw eh nehT .I did os dna
?wohemos meht ekil emoceb ot hkrrL decroF
.doog yrev si tI .russehK ,uoy knaht I<"
.tuo teg ot eganam did I fi neve ,srewsna yna teg t'ndluow I dnA
".siht raeh ot diarfa tsomla m'I"
.os od ot yppah em ekam ton did tI
.su fo eno ylno eht ma I erehw kcab og oT
">.si nalc ym fo tser eht dna ehs erehw si
,sneila rehto dna
llits saw I ,em llits saw I
.ylleb ym ni ,dloc tlef I
.uoy si tI .arruW<"  .og em tel eh nehw detnioppasid saw I
.yawa raf tsuj saw ronrevog eht fi ro
,mih no eye esolc a gnipeek eno on htiw moor elttil ralimis a ni kcuts saw eh fI
,segassem rof pmocinim eht gnikcehc tpek I
tuoba gnuoy saw I nehw em thguat yeht ffuts dlo eht rebmemer ot deirt I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.aklU nalc on si erehT<"
.niaga tas dna ,decap dna
niaga su ees reven dluow uoy su dlot uoY
.doots I erehw morf ton ro ekam-ecnaillA erew yeht fi llet t'ndluoc I
.tey ton ,kool ot nrut t'ndid I
dnuorg eht ot nwod gnibmilc em taeb wohemos ecuaStoH
.era uoy ereh tuB
.oot hkrrL ot ecnaillA eht gnignirb saw eh tahT
.snamuh naht tnereffid os deklaw llits yeht tub
.yrd dna nworb won ,neerg lavitsef remmus eht ni thgir
.hguoht ,yats dluoc I<" ,dias I
">.pihs ecaps sih ni uoy rof gnitiaw mih dnif lliw uoY<"
.tey toN .lrans a etiuq toN
htaerb peed a koot russehK  ">.russehK aklU era uoY .ereh si rehtoM .ereh era uoY
.pu gnidnats kcab dna sredluohs ym fo ruf eht tlef dna ,dehtees I
?ereh no gniog si tahW
">.hcum rehtaew ruo ekil t'nseod ereh dneirf yM .yaw eht daeL
.emit eht kcehc ot osla tub
.og ot ti detcepxe dah I woh rO
.elims-flah fo tros suoicilam a ni
.dnuorg eht tih teef ym nehw
.sretsis dna srehtorb ruoy dna ,rehtaf ruoy si os dnA .si ehS<"
ecanem htiw em sdrawot hcram dluow rehtaf ym woh fo em dednimer yeht fi neve
,woleb lavitsef A
?ffo teg syug uoy od nehW
.deohce I ">,gnorts eviL<"
.swen eht no pu hctac ,sknird wef a evah dluoc eW .em ot thgir lla mees uoY
.yks eht ni gninihs lraT htiw
.gnitiaw su toohs ot uoy gnicrof si reveohw peek ot tnaw t'ndluoW
">?ot em ecudortni dluoc uoy retsis a evah uoy fo rehtie od
.noitcaer a tog I taht ,dnoces a rof ,thguoht I
.flesmih pots dluoc eh erofeb trons ecuaStoH draeh I
">?won uoy htiw evil ehs seoD ?ehs si erehW
.erus t'nsaw I ,tahw nI
"?uoy ot od yeht did tahw oS" ,mih deksa I
.epacse ot gniyrt tuoba thguoht I
.gnihtemos trats ot detnaw eh srae sih morf ees dluoc I
,emac rewsna on tuB
?thgir lla si dneirf namuh ym erus ekam uoy nac ,hO
.enot sih ekil t'ndid I
">.elcnu ,dnatsrednu I<"
.gnitiaw redael eht tsuj dnuof dna
.emas eht llits erew tsael ta nu'hkrrL ew
,snopaew ygrene lennosrep-itna ekil dekool esehT
.deffurg dna deddon eH
.ti fo esnes eht ees dluoc I tuB
.tibro ni llits tub ,dnuorg eht ffo erew eW
...tfel eh nehw erew yeht sa emas eht ton erew sgniht taht dnuof dna
">.yaw rieht fo tuo teg tonnac ew dnA
.ereht ecneulfni fo tnuoma emos htiw ecnaillA eht ni nosrep suomaf yleugav a
.reveileb eurt a fo ecnedifnoc gniyonna eht dah eH
.rebmemer uoy sa emas eht ton era sgniht taht dnif ot sneila eht gnoma emit ruoy morf kcab emoc oT .gnittespU
.nu'hkrrL lla fo doog eht rof ,eciov eno htiw kaeps ot nrael eW<"  .deksa I
">.rebmemer I naht retteB
.ytpme s'ti dna ,tsrif esuoh eht ot tnew I
.ecalp t'ndluoc I tnecca na dah eH
.ni tis dluow sredle eht taht staes nevow-deer ediw eht dna
...em evag ehs kool eht nees evah dluohs uoy dna knird a rof tuo reh ksa ot deirt I !oot elameF
.elahxe lufworros
.kihker sih deppis dna deddon eH
...mmrh oot semitemos si nuhkeS .taht rof seigolopa yM<"
".ereht nwod ffo ssa ym gnirevihs saw I elihw aedi siht dah I os ,kO"
.hsilgnE kaeps t'ndid yeht sseug I tub
.sedis sih ot kcab smra sih deppord eh dna
,flesym tcartsid oT
.hkrrL tub nalc oN
.zzub ruoy rewsna t'ndid I ecnis wenk uoy sseug I hcihw ,esolc ytterp em gnihctaw erew yeht ,hO"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
hkrrL gninrut ydaerla saw
.llahnalC eht ot kcab gniklaw detrats dna
">.uoy etarapes lliw ew ro tnelis yatS
.neppah ti ees ton did uoy os ,meht htiw yawa tnew uoY
,gniteerg ni daerps swalc
.tep tsol a ekil mih tuoba gniklat em draeh eh fi dam os eb dluow ecuaStoH
.noisnep yvan ecnaillA na tog I .ti rof doog m'I
.meht fo xis ekiL
.noisserpxe ym ni ti gniees ,deddon eH
.ton od ,em ot smees ti ,uoy dnA<"
,llahnalC aklU eht fo tnorf ni saw tI
,ti wenk I dna taht etar t'ndid eH
,yllanif nehw elbuort lautca gnikam dna rood eht no gnidnuop fo tniop eht ta tsomla saw I
redluohs eht ni mih dekcams mih ot txen eno eht tub
.X rettel namuh gib a ekil
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,yrraH yb
">.ecnaillA ruoy ot denruter dna spihs ecaps ruoy otni kcab debmilc dneirf namuh ruoy dna uoy fi
.serugif nu'hkrrL ynam htiw
?em rof redro na ni tup syug uoy naC
">.hkrrL sediseb nalc yna rO
.ecaf ew regnad eht wonk ew mih ot sknahT
.oot mih ot klat ot tnaw I .tcefrep s'tahT<" ,dias I
.nalc eno otni tenalp eht etinu ot deganam evah tsum enoemoS
taht saW .tsrif ta ylmraw os em democlew dah eH
">.yas ot evah yeht tahw raeh ot tnaw I
.hkrrL no tsixe t'ndid noitisop eht esuaceb ylbaborp ,drow hsilgnE eht fo noisrev delgnam a ekil saw ti
.nwo ruoy gnicnelis naem dluow tI<"
.esae ta dna mlac yletelpmoc demees ,dnah rehto eht no ,eH
.su fo owt ,meht fo ruof erew ereht ,yawyna rettam t'ndiD
"?gniiks neeb reve uoy evaH
.sraey ni nu'hkrrL rehtona nees t'nevah I
?meht rof gnithgif saw I elihw kcab ym dniheB
"--ecnis degnahc evah sgniht ekil skooL
.enod ydaerla si ti tuB .su ecrof ot elbaronoh oot sevlesmeht kniht yehT .oN<"
.won ,ereh m'I !tsol ton m'I<"
,hsilgnE ni em ot derumrum ecuastoH
",enirevloW ,detnaw uoy yaw eht og t'ndid taht yrros yllaer m'I"
.ffuts ytilauq saw siht llet dluoc I tub
">?eciov eno taht nioj I nac dnA<"
,dlrowemoh sih ot kcab ti edam enirevloW
">.eman ym syekcal ruoy dlot I
.enod tsuj dah yeht goj elttil eht morf ria eht ni gniggof htaerb rieht
fo trap lanif dna
,detiaw dna tas I oS
.yas ot evah I ,ecin tlef tI
.emac hsilgnE kaeps did taht eno elihw a retfa dnA
,eciffo s'ronrevog eht ot del htap ym ,mret trohS
edis eno no hteet prahs sih fo wef a dewohs dna
,revo si raw ruoY
.pots ,arruW!arruWro
.dehgual eH  ".emit siht su rof kcip dluohs uoy ebyaM" .ti tuoba kniht ot nugeb neve t'ndah I
.gniteerg ym denruter tsomla dah ohw eno ehT
?naem uoy od tahW<"
.ti fo tnorf ni staes erew erehT
.yawa saw I elihw degnahc dah sgnihT
.yrgnuh dna deracs dna dloc ylbaborp s'eH
.feihc ,os yas uoy fI<"
;klaw meht dehctaw I
,esoht fo emos rof og dluoc I
.mih rewsna ot em rof detiaW
,did uoy dias ecno uoy sa
">.llew dna efas si rehtom em llet tsael tA .elcnu ,esaelP<"
.erom emos decap dnA .pmocinim eht dekcehc dnA .decap dnA
.toidi sselruf ynniks a saw su fo eno dnA
.rehtom ym rof dnA
.emoh ym rof gnikool emac I .oN<"
.htiw tlaed eb lliw tI<"
">.sevlesruo dnefed ot od tsum ew tahw dnA
.srats eht otni ffo neht