"?em htiw emoc ot tnaw uoY
",dias I tahw s'tahT"
,dias yllanif dna deffuh I
.sreniatnoc nepo-nrot fo hcnub a rof tpecxe
.terpretni ot woh wonk t'nod
".sruo naht regnol leef sruoY
,detaeper I ",sneila 'nikcuF
".won ruf ni derevoc era lla'y yhw ees nac I ,haeY"
.raw eht tuoba tihs a evig t'now yehT" .detrons I
",hkrrL"  "--uoy thguoht I
.meht deksa ew oS
,ekil eb dluow gnimocemoh fo tnemom siht tahw tuoba saedi fo tol a dah dah I
,ytic eht ni llahnalC eht ot og ot deen eW"
".ereht kcab gniog reven erew uoy taht enoyreve dlot uoy thguoht I
.dias sredle eht ,gnisol era uoy esruoc fo lleW
.sselruf tsomla dna yriw dna niht saw
.gnippots reven ,gninetaerht reven ,gniklat reveN
.ecaps ecnaillA ni detnaw ew erehwyna og dluoc eW
.spmuj neewteb sllul eht gnirud mih hcaet ot gniyrt neeb dah I sesarhp rehto eht fo yna rO
.dlrowemoh ym fo retniw eht ni gnilever
.edistuo saw eno oN
ecnaillA rieht dna snamuh esehT
.nu'hkrrL rehto gniees ssim I"
.ria eht gniffins ,daeh ym detlit I dna
.knird sih gnisiar ,dias eh
,thgin eht ni tsethgirb dewolg ti esuaceb
yojne esaelP  .yrruFoS no
.daeh sih koohs eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
".shtnom elpuoc a naht erom ereht yats ot yenom eht evah t'nod uoy gniwratS ruoy lles uoy sselnu dnA
.mih emalb t'ndluoc I sseug I
.srotisiv eht ees ot ytic eht ot edor lla ew dna tif dluow esle reveohw dna snisuoc dna sretsis dna srehtorb htiw tropsnart a no deppoh I
.nworg saw I erehW .thguoht I
"?em htiw emoc ot tnaw llitS"
.hcT"  ".gnihtemos ro srehposolihp roirraw tsificap
ytpme saw yrtnap ehT
.htmraw oN .gnihtaerb dna spetstoof nwo ruo tpcexe dnuos oN
,hguone elbisnes tub gnikool-ynnuf erew yeht thguoht dna deffurg dna deddon ew dnA
"?evael ot noisiced ruoy ekat ylimaf ruoy d'woh ,hu oS"  ".taht tuoba gnikniht pots t'ndluoc I
.revo lla su tnes ,pu su ekorb yeht dnA
yltsom tub ,skcasniks uoy ot naem dna yracs lla kool yam ew oS
!oreh raw a er'uoY
".t'nac uoy ,oN"  "--tahw enigami t'nac I sseug I .enirevloW ,yrroS"
,ti ekil ylbaborp uoy sa mraw sa toN
--edam ti dnuos ehT
"?pu nioj uoy d'yhw oS"
.em tuohtiw ti deganam evah dluow reven stoidi sselruf uoY
hguone thgirb dezalb lraT .hkrrL sdrawot
.ycehporp siht ta debrutsid
.mrofinu rieht revo lla ti fo flah gnillips tuohtiw
,hmmrrh ,eb thgim ti tub
.warts a hguorht enim morf ward gnol a gnikat yb ti derevoc I .deil I ",wonk t'noD"
.rehto hcae -nedrag taht ni
"--su ekil skool fo tros taht lamina dliw emos dah uoy esuaceb tsuJ .snamuH
.sredluohs dna kcen ym fo kcab eht derevoc taht ruf fo enam eht tuo deffulf dna daeh ym koohs I ".gnol
,tnemeerga na hcaer tonnac uoy dna ,htgnerts rieht hctam tonnac uoy fI
.ereh tog ew nehw eb dluow ti nosaes tahw wonk t'ndid I" .dennirg I
.edistuo enoyna ot evisserpmi eb ot tnaem ton erew semoH
.tenalp ruoy no sroirraw evarb lla erew uoy thguoht I
.tsael ta sredle nalc eht desaelp hcihw
.semit ynam detool dna dehcraes neeb dah ecalp eht ekiL
.niatpaC ,ti tog uoY"  .denraw I
krad saw edisni ecaps ehT
.dias I tahw tnaem I ,oN"  .dereffo I
.taht tuoba nettogrof dah I
.yxalag eht evas pleh ot tog I .on lleH"
...tnereffid dah tsuj eW .ecnaillA eht ni seiceps rehto yna sa trams sa tsuj er'eW
.mih thguat evah t'ndluohs I taht sgniht enecsbo fo lufdnah a dna esoht ,lleW
nepo srood htiw smoor ytpme tsuJ
.snamuh tsom ot gninetaerht dednuos eciov lamron ym taht kciuq ytterp denrael d'I
snamuh tsom taht dnik ehT
senigne eht delliK
.srotcev noitresni ro ecnaraelc gnitseuqer rehtob t'nod dnA .t'now uoY"  ".flesti
.spihs tekcip ro sresiurcelttab ro sreirrac teelf tnaig oN
lebal a htiw xob elttil a ni ti tuP
.lios fo sdolc eht ot sdapregnif erab ym dehcuot dna nwod dehcuorc I
,evael dna pu tsuj d'eh fi derednow I
.drah taht gnikrow rof toh oot dna ,remmus saw tI
.esuoh lautca eht otni del taht eno eht
edistuo eht morf oS
,yhw rednow ot em ot rucco t'ndid tI
*****   ".enirevloW ,dne eht lit' namgniw ruoy m'I"
.reetnulov nu'hkrrL elgnis a tuohtiw emoh og dluow yeht thguoht I ,emit eht tA
...a ekil snaem fo tros tI" ,denialpxe I
,detanimretxe eb lla lliw nu'hkrrL eht dnA
".tekcaj a gnirb ot em denraw evah dluoc uoY"
.yawyna ,ecuaStoH roF
.enon saw ereht taht ees dluoc I dna
".ni doof worg uoy tahw s'taht ,htrae tuB
saw ecnedifnoc yna htiw yas dluoc eh lla fi nevE .foorp gniviL
dnuora gninrut ,dias I
"?neht ,tuo derugif lla su toG"
,ecuaStoH saw ereh dnA
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,yrraH yb
dnuora gnikool ysub saw I
.elzzum ym fo egdirb eht debbur I  .niaga deksa eh
.ereht tuo ssenizarc neila taht fo trap laer a ekil saw eh tub
.yllaer t'nod yeht ,oN"  ".ykoops s'tI
,rood etisoppo eht rof dedaeh I ".enog
.drow dlo na s'tI
?snus rehto ot levart nac taht snalc ot evig ylbissop ew dluoc pleh tahW ?pleH
.nalc neila emos nioj nu'hkrrL eno yna ekam t'ndluoc yeht neht neve dnA .aklU nalC ylno
.dniheb tfel I esoht naht retteb ebyam
.egdir eht sdrawot htap retsevrah a otno dna
.reffo eht gnikam ,deksa I
.gnilles emac yeht adnagaporp denmad eht fo esuaceB"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.flesti tenalp eht morf tpecxe snoissimsnart oidar on tsomla ,slortap metsys yna pu gnikcip ton m'I
".sseug I ,ylimaf ruoy ssim uoY"
,ecnis ebyam dna ,erofeb snamuh nees d'yehT
,loof a era uoy ,kO"
.edisni tnew ew nehT
.mrofinu ym fo gel eht otno mlap ym ffo noitasnednoc eht depiw dna rab eht no knird ym tes neht
.ti ees uoy sa noos sa gnihtyreve yfissalc ot kciuq os era lla uoy
,moor-tuo eht sa dloc dna krad sa tsuJ
tnelis deyats dna
"?eb ti evael uoy dluow ,mutnegrA dias I fI"
.yllaretil sdrow sih gnikat
.sgniwratS ruo ot kcab yaw eht lla
,metsys renni eht sdrawot spmuj-inim ruo dehcnys dna pu deknil dah eW
.od ot detnaw I tahw fo tuo flesym klat ot gniyrt llits saw I
.rekaeps tipkcoc ym hguorht ni emac eciov s'ecuaStoH
?thgir ,sehtolc ruoy no tnaw t'nod uoy gnihtemos s'tI .ytrid s'ti llew ...si
.su dlot yeht dnA
.eugra t'ndid ecuaStoH
?wonk ot tnaw uoy yhW"
,dias uoy ekil tub seod ti haeY"
.dereffo erew taht dnammoc ecnaillA htiw sboj sutats-hgih ysae eht koot dna deyats wef A
hkrrL s'tahw oS"
.yas dluoc eh gnihtyna t'nsaw erehT
,dias yeht ,ytic ruo dekcip dah yehT
.detrons I .yawa dekool eH
.slevel elpitlum rof dnuorgrednu peed tnew dna egdir a fo edis eht otni tliub saw
.dnim ym fo sretaw ecafrus eht ot esir neve t'ndid ti taht
".trid tnaem tsuj htrae thguoht I"
...fo epahs eht dna elzzum eht dnuora ruf krad ehT .elttil a ,kO
.hguoht ,aedi doog a si siht kniht llits I
,warts ym morf knird gnol rehtona koot I
.edisni remraw eb ll'tI"
.llah lartnec eht ffo smoor eht otni
ecuaStoH dlot I oS
?kreL ot kcaB ?yllaeR"
,gnihtemos yas ot detnaw ecuaStoH wenk I
.snalc gnirobhgien eht fo eno htiw edart ot rehtegot tnempihs a gnitteg ,esuoheraw s'rehtaf ym ni gnikrow saw I
,seert eht fo sepahs eht ta
".dennuhs teg uoy dna tuc teg uoy
,selims gib ym fo eno mih evag I nehT ".em
.teiuq deyats ecuaStoH
?dnatsrednu ro eveileb dluow yeht taht meht llet I dluoc tahW
".ti pleh nac uoy fi lebal taht egnahc reve reven dna
".enirevloW ,emoh s'eno on ekil skooL"  .nepo ediW
.demees ti ,hturt ehT
.motsuc namuh eht ni
.si triD .tnereffid s'ti
nevig neeb d'ew seoreh raw sA
.reve ,erehwyna nu'hkrrL erom on eb dluow ereht neht dnA
.tnemeerga ym deffurg I
.sroolf eht no ffuts modnar fo selip dna
.llew sa nepo saw tI
.tcefrep tlef llihc ehT
.gnipoohw dna pihs ym dnuora selcric ni gninnur dna gnipmuj ekil tlef I
.gnitseretni dna tnereffid tsuJ
.smetsys rats rehto fo snezod otni
".emoh og ot gniog m'I kniht I"
,reduol gnitteg eciov ym leef dluoc I ".niaga
.esuoh s'rehtom ym raen dleif a ni gnidnal eb d'ew
,ecuaStoH ekilnU
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,ti tuoba gnihtemos od t'ndid enoemos fi dnA
.saw ti erehwyreve ,emas eht lla saw tI
"?gnidaeh uoy erehw oS"
.dednal tsrif dah pihs ecnaillA eht nehw ereht t'nsaw I
.yllaer ,esoprup nO
,retlehs ot ,sseug I enoyna ro ,sselnalc eht rof eb ot desoppus si ecalp sihT" ,denialpxe I
.ereht modsiw saw ereht ebyam taht dewolla dna
.niarb ym htiw deretsiger taht erutangis thgil eht ni gnihtemos saw ereht ebyam tsuj tuB
dleif eht fo tser eht ssorca deklaw eW
".namgniw ruoy m'I
.flesti naht tnereffiD
,htrof dna kcab thgil elttil ym tpews I
.rehtegot nalc tolip ruo fo trap llams emos peek ot gniyrt
"?elpoep uoy era evitimirp woh tsuj ,aohW"
",gniklat eht od em tel
.krad eb t'ndluohs moor-tuo ehT .haeY"
"?gnihtemos ro llebrood a ekil ereht si oS"
,eb thgim uoy erehw rettam on emas eht dekool srats dna ecapS
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.gnol era sretniw ruo tuB
.enirevloW ,ti teg I"  ".haeY"
.llird gnidnal a saw ti ekil
.dleif eht fo lios nezorf yhcnurc eht otno dna
.teiuq yrev t'nsi hcihw ,erehpsomta na ni eb dluoc gniwratS a sa teiuq sa dna
,elttil a mrofinu ym deppiznu neve I
.ti fo tuo neve rO
.mrofinu fo tuo ekil saw I tahw
.dettimda I ",oN"  "?ydaer uoY"
.sPM eht llac ot deen ot gniog saw eh fi gnirednow ylbaborp
.dewohs ecnaillA eht htgnerts hcum woh rettam on ,gnorw eb ot eerga tsuj ot gniog saw taht gnihtemos t'nsaw tlatseG ehT
.tlatseG eht dellac yeht gniht eht tuobA
.etisoppo etelpmoc yM
.ecnaillA rieht demrof taht secar rehto fo snezod eht dna snamuh eht htiw gnola
elbidercni os saw flesym eno gnieb fo thguoht ehT
,hgual ot nrut ym saw tI
seirots sih fo tsom dnif nac uoy tub ,seman tnereffid wef a rednu sehsilbup dna setirw ohw ,yrraH yb
.rewsna taht gnitcepxe erew yeht ekil demees snamuh ehT
tlef wohemos su deteerg taht rats egnaro thgirb eht ,llitS
",ereh deneppah tahw tuo dnif
.retaw dna doof elttil a teg
deffurg dna deddon sredle ehT
.deretnuoc snamuh eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.uoy ekil yltcaxe skooL"
,noziroh ruo dnoyeb kool ot nosaer a dah reven dah eW
.tsael ta scinosrepus on tuB
,dias I ",did I ,haeY"
.srethgif gniwratS ruo fo ydotsuc neve dna evael etinifedni
".gnola uoy htiw reisae
".ereht eb ll'ew dna pmuj erom enO"
htob htiw gnirutseg elihw "?siht otni eb lliw nemow ruoy kniht uoy oD" ,deksa eH
.siht ekil erew meht fo enon tub
sih tsniaga ti deknilc dna ssalg ym deveirter I
.tnew ti sa raf sa
.nehctik niam eht ot tog I nehw deppots I
.nepo syawla s'tI
ngisllac gnidnuos-ycips sih etipsed ohw
.enots noitadnuof
,tlatseG eht thgif meht pleh ot
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
1 traP ,yrraH yb
"!detpecca egnellahC"
.eldnah eht no dellup dna daeh ym koohs I
"?gnidaeh uoy erehW"  2 fo
yawynA" .dennirg eh
,ereht nwod saw ti tuB
".syawedis og lla llits dluoc sihT
.eson ym ot ti thguorb dna
?tibro ekam neve ew erofeb noitpecer elitsoh a tuoba deirrow uoY"
tuo dnif ot tnaw ot hguone evitcartta em dnuof selamef namuh ynam ton ytilaer nI
--ria retniw eht fo llems eht dna
.ot mih tnaw yllautca t'ndid I dnuof I
.detnaw yeht tahw meht deksa ew oS
".sseug I ,htraE ekil fo dniK"
.noissim tcatnoc tsrif taht no dah ecnaillA eht ekil noisserpmi gib a ekam ro
.rethgiarts pu tas dna sworbeye sih desiar eH
".ecuaStoH ,drah t'nsaW"
,hkrrL fo lla rof kaeps t'ndluoc yeht dias aklU nalC fo sredle eht tuB .ecnaillA eht nioj ot hkrrL fo lla detivni snamuh ehT
.ot ti tnaem I naht elitsoh erom dednuos ylbaborp taht enot a ni ,deksa I
.eb t'ndluoc tlatseG eht taht gniht eno eht saw taht dnA
.thgir taht tog uoY"
,em wenk eH .dehgual eH
".sseug nac uoy kniht I hO"
.llihc eht morf ton tub ,derevihs I
."ool eht s'erehW" dna "uoy knahT" ,"olleH"
.niaga meht fo eno elgnis a was reven I
staerht elbissop ylno eht htiw laed ot yaw tseb eht tuo dekrow ydaerla dah dna
.hkrrL no neeb s'ti sraey ynam woh swonk ohW
,meht nioj ot dehsiw ohw enoyna dna
.won trons ot nrut siH
.sthguoht gnirednaw dennuts ym fo tuo dellup ,pu dekool I
.emac ew yaw eht kcab nur ot ton gniyrt dna
non ym htiw deifsitas mees t'ndid eH
,pihs s'ecuaStoH morf gnihcaorppa spetstoof raeh dluoc I
".retfa tnemtaert lacidem deen dluow uoy dnA .oN"
,tnaw uoy od tahw oS
",taht regoR" ,dias eH
”remmuS fo eM ot kaepS“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
hkrrL ot tog ti nehw
.drawkwa gnitteg saw su neewteb ecnelis ehT
.flesti ro meht fo erom ekam ot sdlrow eritne gnitsevrah ylsseldne ,dnim sseldnim
.elzzum ym htiw denoitom I
.derettam taht ereht emoclew erew taht esoht dna edisni eht saw tI
,gnirats rednetrab eht thguac I
.em htiw ecuaStoH dah I tsael tA
.ygrene fo etsaw a si gnithgiF
,remmus eht fo dne eht litnu yats dluoc yeht fi deksa yehT
.neht meht htiw evael dluoc
.hpmmH"  "?xob a ni ohw gnittup s'ohw woN"
.rewsna ot em rof gnitiaw ,em ta gnirats llits saw eH .dewollaws
.su gnihctaw neeb dah yeht gnol woh rednow su edam hcihw ,yltsom
.yaw rieht eht fo tuo teg uoy ro esol uoy
.deirrow dna detcartsid ,deerga I ",haeY"
lwarb lautca na ni pu dne uoy fI
".uoy morf ti tuoba raeh yeht fi ecnaillA eht gninioj tuoba sdnim rieht egnahc ll'yeht ebyaM
.yaw taht ti ekil eW"
.tuhs htuom sih tpek eh dalg saw I tub
eno sa detca tub eno on yb dellortnoc erew taht senihcam ehT
...ekil sa senirevlow fo hcnub a enigami ot em rof drah tsuJ"
.ekops I sa gof fo slirdnet elttil edam htaerb yM ".yaw
.I saw oS  .ffo eb ot regae
rehtegot dleif eht ni nwod tes eW
?ko ,htap emas eht swollof ecar yreve toN !yeH"
dah ew ekil citpilce eht ffo ni depmuj eW
.ylrae krow ffo teg ot deveiler yltsom saw I dna
.esuoh eht otni dedaeh I
dluoc namuh a ylno sa ssalg llat eht morf thgiarts ,sih morf knard ecuaStoH
?tuoba deirrow uoy era tahW"
.pleh ruo detnaw yeht dias snamuh eht dnA
,tsehc ym fo ruf eht fo emos gnirab
,deksa yllanif eh ,deppots I dna rood eht ot tog ew nehW
.hsiftalf a ekil gnikrul
.ti no tnuoc t'noD"
,gnirettacs saw nalc ehT
".em ffo edils taht selamef eht lla hctac dna ,ruf liat ym edir ot tnaw tsuj uoY" ,dereffo I
.nepo dewalc ylleb rieht steg eno on dna ,thgir si ohw deerga s'ti litnu rehto hcae ot gninetaerht kool tsuj ew
.dniw eht ni sevael ekil enog ydaerla erew tsoM
.epacsdnal eht fo sroloc detum eht
"?dniheb gnihtyreve gnivael terger uoY"  .eno dlo na rO
.remmus feirb eht gnirud ereh gniworg neeb dah revetahw fo stnanmer eht hguorht welb dniw ehT
.doom ylrus ym fo derit
,hguoht ,tsaf daerps dlrow rehtona morf sneila fo lavirra eht fo droW
.dlrow ruo no efil fo ecruos eht gnieb rof ti detcepser ew tuB
wols ni emac eW  .sgnilbis dna stnerap ym htiw klat ot ni desolc sdworc eht erofeb emit elttil a detnaw I dna
,htrae ym si sihT
".aedi emos evah attog uoy ,enirevloW nom'C" .rewsna-
.flesmih ot smra sih gnigguh elihw dias eh ",hu yeH"
*****   ".namgniw eht tsuj m'I ,ytrap ruoy s'tI
.denigami evah reve dluoc nalc ym fo enon taht secalp morf kcab gnimoc ,saw I ereh woN
".did ew tahw tuo tuoba raeh yeht retfa edarap rehtona teg ll'ew ebyaM .uoy evol ll'yehT
,hsilgnE ni ti dellac dah I sa ,esuoh ehT
".seitiroirP .wonk uoy
.I did os dna pmoc-tsirw sih otni tliub thgil eht no dekcilc eH  ".dloc siht rO
,sregnif owt neewteb ti dehsurc dna debbur
",esuoh eht ot raf oot ton s'tI"
",detnaw uoy fi ,gninnur retaeh eht htiw pihs ruoy ni yats dluoc uoY"
.sretiurcer ecnaillA eht htiw tfel I ecnis sraey 21 neeb s'ti tuB" ,delworg I
.dnim ym ni lla ylbaborp saw ti hguoht ,tnereffid
.rediw dennirg I ".eganam ll'uoY
,egaugnal ruo kaeps dluoc yehT
.gnisol erew yeht dna
tfarc ruo fo seilleb eht morf nwod debmilc dna
,ereht nwod teg ew nehw tuB .tnioP
.lraT ot dewo I ,saw I gnihtyrevE .rats emoH
.ecitcarp fo tol a tuohtiw thgir ti yas t'ndluoc ylbaborp eh hguoht ,mih detcerroc I
.sgniwratS owt ruo tsuj saw ti sa ,snoissim gnituocs ruo fo eno ekil tlef tI
.oreh raw a er'uoy tub
.ecnaillA eht pleh ot dereetnulov dna adnagaporp eht thguob taht su fo neetfif tuoba erew erehT
.gnilooc yldipar latem fo dnuos knit-knit eht sa llew sa
.yawyna eromyna toN .taht ekil gnihtyna ro nus eht pihsrow t'ndid eW
”remmuS fo eM ot kaepS“
nretsic eht fo tuo pmup ot rewop dedeen ti sa retaw eht gniyrt rehtob t'ndid I
.yromem tnatsid a saw emit tsrif eht rof dlrow ym gnivael tlef dah I ewa laitini eht dna
.em htiw emoc ot tnaw did eH
.su dlot yeht dnA
.enola em ro ,ti evael ot elbanu ,deksa eh
,nosinu tcefrep ni
.revo erew sedarap eht dna raw eht taht won pu gnikaerb saw nordauqs ehT
,dias eh ",yaw eht daeL"
?su pots dluow ohW
.emit eht ta su ot esnes edam tI
.suovren snamuh edam taht dnuos taht otni gnigde
.hcum ekil kool t'ndid ti
,tuo nap t'ndid aedi ym fI
.eno wen a dnif ot tfel erew eW .trapa gnillaf
.ti od uoy woh teg t'nod llits I" ,delkcuhc eH
.yltcaxe ton tuB .fo pot no dliub uoy elbats gnihtemoS
.og ot dennalp I erehw wonk neve t'ndid eh dnA
.rab ediskcod eht ni sdaeh wef a denrut taht esion ytaorht wol a
.revetahw rO .uoy rO .su ekil kniht t'nseod tI
.su naht tnereffid era uoy esuaceb dias yeht dnA
.elzzum derruf-krad ym tsniaga hteet etihw prahs lla
.enog s'rewop eht ekil s'ti tuB
.ecuaStoH detpmorp "...tuB"
".nam sneila 'nikcuF
.ylimaf s’enirevloW ot deneppah tahw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,niaga deksa sredle eht
”remmuS fo eM ot kaepS“
.ecnelis laicos ekil hcum t'ndid yeht taht wonk ot hguone gnol rof snamuh gnoma gnivil neeb d'I
,yaw eht fo tuo erehwon eb lliw erehT
".dlrow eht snaem tsuj ti woN
.thgir ti yas t'ndluoc llits eH  "?yawyna ,naem
.namgniw ym deksa "?gnorw gnihtemoS"
.dehgual sredle ehT
sredle nalc eht htiw laed ot tnaw yllaer t'ndid I
,tlatseG eht gnithgif erew
.ereht gniog ton er'uoY"
,nedrag dellaw elttil a ni devil ew dna
.'etacinummoc ot eruliaf' a fo tluser eht si gnithgif lautca kniht yehT
.ti ot desu neeb evah dluohs ecuaStoH tuB
".uoy rewsna ot eno on s'erehT
si tniop eht yawyna
,kciuq ytterp dnuora teg dluow droW
.xis ym gnihctaw enoemos evah ot doog eb dluow ti ebyam
.evitcartta em dnif yllaer t'ndid yeht ebyam dnA
.eno edun a neve ,hcaeb a no gniyl uoy enigami t'nac I
.dnuora knird sih gnirrits elihw ecuaStoH deksa
.hgual gniraor a htiw niaga rednetrab eht delttar I  .flesmih ta sdnah
,knuhc elttil a koot I
".kcab gniog tuoba deirrow er'uoy yhw s'taht dnA"
.ti ta gnikool diova ot dah I taht
.deddon dna eson gninedder sih ssorca tsirw sih debbur eH
.stenalp rehto esoht lla ot did ti ekil tibro morf ecalp elohw eht 'desnaelc' evah dluow ti