,dehsinav dah seye s’aneyh eht ni kool ecreif eht taht was dna ,ezag eht nruter ot kcen sih denarc eH
.ylthgit mih gnizeeuqs rehtorb redlo sih
.exa taht fo thgis eht nopu nekorb dah
,wap s’netram ylredle eht otni sgnaf ynit sih knus dah ilevuK ”!hgra“ keirhs ythgimla na htiw egatsoh sih morf yawa mra sih gniknay
,roines sih sretniw net ,xof reggib eht dehctaw eH
,ylsuoibud deksa ilevuK ”?niaga ,elbuort otni nettog uoy evaH“
.liated elttil yreve ni gnikat dna
,gnidniw eht dewollof eH
,dum eht morf esor ilevuK
,hcamots s’arakaS tsniaga daeherof sih desserp dna
yawa raf seert hguorht deohce rednuht fo murht ehT  xoFarakaS yb ”niaR gnirpS“   yojne esaelP   radnelaC pU-niP syaD noitacaV s’evitarepooC ediseriF —   .emit gnol a ni erutnevda dedeen hcum tsrif ruoy no uoy gnikat eb lliw niart ruoy dna niaga emitremmus s’tI .ria mraw eht fo htaerb peed a gnikat ,hcneb eht morf esir dna esactius ruoy ni koob ruoy tup uoY .hcaorppa s’niart eht syarteb sekarb fo laeuqs ehT 04:90  ?trats serutnevda lla erehw naht trats ot retteb erehw dnA .1202 fo serutnevda eht rof daeha gnikool trats ot emit s'ti ,esolc a ot semoc 0202 sA
.stoob sih otni pees ot nugeb dah ti ,esroW
”?kniht uoy od tahw ,oS“
,redluohs s’arakaS no wap a tup dna drawrof deppets aneyh gnikool-yraew won eht ,daetsnI
nirg yhtoot a laever ot guh eht fo eerf gnillup
redluohs sih revo exa sih gnipeek
.tohsrae fo tuo saw rehtorb sih litnu detiaw dna dehctaw ilevuK
.gniralf slirtson reh
,ytsenohsid deyarteb aneyh eht tuoba gnihtoN
gnihsur erofeb delkcuhc eh raews dluoc ilevuK dna
.kao dlo suoicsul ylbanosaesnu tub
.teem edart gniltsub eht hguorht rehtorb elttil sih dna reh dreh ot detpmetta dna
.hteet reh neewteb dehctulc llits ssarg fo tfut a
.reh truh dluow taht gnihtyna pu-gud t’ndah eram yarg-elppad eht deifsitas
,yks eht ot desiar ezag eulb-citcra sih tpek eH
,delworg ilevuK ”.thgirhtrib ruo s’tI“
,pu-delknirw ecaf s’arakaS ”…llew -oN“
.thgirpu detlob netram ylredle eht sa
stoob niksrevaeb siH
,loof dlo emos yb dleh gnieb saw eH“
.egdelwonk fo htlaew
,mraw eht demialcxE ”!emac uoy ,ronoC“
A	 .krow reh ta nwod yltnetnoc delims ehs sa ylitniad tsomla
.edih reednier denniks ylhserf a morf hself fo sderhs eparcs ylluflliks ydal-raeb nworb
,tnilf fo knuhc eraps a tpek d’eh ylno fI
.htmraw htiw xof elttil eht dellif
tnurg a htiw swaptoof sih ot flesmih dehsup arakaS
,ksa ot htuom sih denepo ilevuK
,revewoh ,revo dellor eh erofeB
,dehsurc ro denworD
.doolb fo gnat teews eht htiw degnit saw eugnot sih litnu
sA	 .stoob rieht tsniaga dehsurb taht nokcarb dna
.rufdaeh s’rehtorb elttil sih gnilffur
,emit siht elkcuhc ytraeh a tuo tel eH
.rae s’xof elttil eht otni delbmum seigolopa
em morf yawa teG“
,hsael s’akkeP no gniggut
,deltrohc arakaS
,ecno ta lla desaec niar ehT
.ecnegilletni s’god a ekil t’nsaw ti tub
,detroter xof redlo ehT
.tsiaw s’aneyh eht sa llat sa gnidnats ylno
,ecnaraeppa ni gniyfirret
ni sevooh reh gud esroh rieht
,netram eht desaeler aneyh eht ,raelc saw eh ecnO
ekoms fo hcnets dirca eht htiw delgnim seidob dehsawnu fo sderdnuh fo rodo ehT
.seraps fo ytnelp htiw meht tfel
,lavitsef gnirps-dim eht ekilnu ton tub
.xof elttil eht dniheb gnihtemos no worran ot demees seye sih nehT
.emas eht lla dehgual eh dna
.triks sih nwod dehsurb eh erofeb trons a htiw eson sih gnipiw
,ylkciuq dedaf niar gnivird fo murd ehT
.fooh tnatculer a htiw htrae eht wap dna
dekcalc swob doowlezah rieht
.tsehc sih ot ylthgit
”.rehtorb elttil ,niw tonnac uoy duef a detrats evah uoy ,hO“
,spil sih tfel rettel tsal eht sA
,kcab elims dna elkcuhc tub pleh t’ndluoc ilevuK
,erus ylimaf saw akkeP
,tsrif ta ysae demees tI
.nruter ni derekcins aneyh ehT
.aneyh eht ta redluohs sih revo kcab gnikool
,esor worbeye s’aneyh ehT ”…ilevuK“
,ruoivas sih dniheb teg ot delbmarcs ilevuK sA
,ebirt gib a morf saw eH
ilevuK dednimer tI
hcleuqs ralimis a saw erehT
,tserof eht hguorht derettacs wons s’retniw fo tsal eht yawa dehsaw dah tI
,detsiser esroh ehT
.ediskcab eros sih debbur dna
,ediw htiw rehtorb sih ta pu derats ilevuK
”.stun og ot rehtorb gib ruoy tnaw uoy sselnu ,neddih dnuow taht peek ,fo gnikaepS“
,nikrej a dna ,htolcniol a ,sgniggel elpmis ni desserd
.daeh s’xof elttil eht sa gib sa sexa taerg ot
.noitceffa dna sguh htiw mih detacoffus dna
elims s’rehtorb sih fo ssendnik eht
.sgiwt ecurps delip fo daetsni sniks morf edam ot-nael gib a ekil dekool taht sretlehs neve dna
.tnadnep edaj a otni srehtaef lwo fo rebmun a gniwes
,yhtlif saw gniggel thgir siH
.noitom lufretsam eno htiw netram eht dna xof eht htob daeheb ot ydaer doots
,arakaS fo eciov railimaf
,elzzum s’ronoC otni thgir eson sih kcuts neve eH
,sniks reednier morf edam uvval gnirepat ,llat
,decarbme dah yeht ecnO
.ilevuK ot stunlezah fo hcuop eht dereffo neht
dum htiw dekac gnimoceb kaolcniar sih
.sgel sih neewteb liat sih htiw
.tserof eht ni erah ro reed elgnis a neeb reven dah ereht hguoht sa
.detnuomsid dna akkeP revo gel sih detfil eh sa eciov sih ni ytisoiruc fo muh a ,deksa arakaS
.flesmih ot ylteiuq delkcuhc eh dna
,swap yrettij etipsed ,teY
mrof delppirc dna revo-dehcnuh siH
.nwod teg ilevuK pleh ot gnireffo
.ydob liarf ylevitpeced s’netram eht tsniaga dekcik dna demriuqs eh sa depley ilevuK ”!-
,sdnuos nezod a htiw gnar srae riehT
,dnuora lla staert eerf ylgnimees eht lla ot dnim on diap akkeP
hcrib gnirewot fo
,sdaehraeps dna sevink etaciled morf
dum fo reyal kciht a
”.enola ilevuK evaeL !akkeP ,hguone s’tahT“
.yletaidemmi wollof ton did eh tub
.niaga deppots dah yeht yhw ees ot mih dnuora gnireep
tnarbiv dna llat doots ti sa
,tcefrep erom neeb evah ton dluoc emit ehT
dehctulc eh hcihw ,stunlezah eht hctac ot mih fo tnorf ni swap sih deppuc dna ,eenk eno no nwod tnew eH
,regnarts eht ecaf ot dnuora deleehw
dekrep srae s’akkeP .saw taht ,murtnat a werht yeht litnU
,esor worbeye na sa smra sih dedlof ronoC
”.emoc ev’uoy raf woh
,rehtorb elttil sih ta pu dekool dna tops eht no denrut neht ,dedda arakaS
,meht htaeneb semarf no dehcterts erew taht sniks eht ekil tsuj
”.kniht I ,hcum ooT“
.riap eht dniheb morf eciov evitatirohtua tey ,yllevarg a delbmuR
.teem edart gniltsub eht otni
,drow hcae no deregnil eh sa hgis a gnitareggaxe ,nageb eh ”,seY“
.mra s’xof elttil sselpleh eht otni swalc denekcalb sih knus eh sa ilevuK revo lla avilas ykcits gnittips ,dessih eH ”!uoY“
,wons eht ni dellever ohw
niht ot nageb seert fo yponac eht sa
”?klat dna klaw nac ew spahrep
kcab xof elttil eht degguh arakaS
”.stunlezah deyenoh emos retfa elbaeerga erom eb ll’ehs kniht I“
.stunlezah erom gnidnamed
.guh a fo reffo eht denilced tub ,gninediw elims sih
.nwod deppord ylluferac dna revo thgiew sih detfihs eh sa
.yawa teg ot regae demees eH
,weiv s’ilevuK gnirucsbo ,snoitseuq deksa dna
,ni depmuj ilevuK
.gel s’ilevuK no gut yltneg ot tuo dehcaer dna
,yawyna kao dlo eht yb teem ot nwonk evah dluohs dneirf siH
.yaw eht fo edis eht ot esroh rieht dellup arakaS
.enips sih pu llihc a tnes tI .traeh gnimoob eht dna
,gniggel sih edisni dum leef dluoc eH
.dniheb regnil ot nugeb dah ilevuK elttil taht eciton ot ysub oot
.sakrap niks laes gnikool tseifmoc eht ni
,tnatsni na ni gnitrap sduolc eht
”.ronoC ,su nioj ot emoclew er’uoY“
krims eltbus a otni kcab dedaf elims ediw sih ,deffuh ronoC
.sliart emag nwonk-llew eht yawa hsaw dna
,edisa meht dehsurb arakaS sa sreviuq rieht ni delttar sworra ehT
,gnirps siht yvaeh erew skcap levart ehT
.desiar worbeye na dna deworran seye
”?-dnif uoy did erehW“
”.niaga uoy ees ot doog s’tI“
,emas eht enod evah dluoc eh hguoht sa tlef ilevuK
.nikskcub e eht ot gnulc won
,slluks hsurc dluoc sevooh esohT
detegdif xof elttil
.hcnilf neve t’ndid netram eht rorroh sih oT
hserf eht fo sduolc pu-gnikcik dna dnuora gnicnarp yllufyalp
,tnecs tsetniaf eht saw tI
drawrof deppets eH
,reed fo slluks eht morf edam
,taefed timda ot fi sa ,neht dnA
.gnivil a rof slluks tilps I ,roirraw a m’I“
.stneregilleb owt eht neewteb morf eerf dellor dna
,sgod sediseb wenk eh erutaerc rehto yna naht retrams erew yeht
,yltfiws noitseuq eht deirrap ronoC
,siht ekil syad ymrots no tub ,drah ti ekam dluow edir hguor ehT
aes eht sdrawot deksihw erew
.redrah etib ot ilevuK gnisuac ylno
~ecaf ot denrut eh litnu
.regnarts eht ecaf ot mih gnicrof ,niaga daeh sih no deknay netram ehT
,tnuom rieht otno kcab debmilc sexof owt ehT
.tnew eh reverehw redneval fo sluftsif worht ot rehto eht desu dna
deppots eh sa nepo gnuh waj s’ilevuK
.eno-yb-eno stunlezah eht pu-elffuns ot nageb neht dna ,enam reh koohs
.gnihtyreve nword ot demees mrots eht
.esroh rieht no denael neht
.thgil neerg gniwolg fo stfahs tnaillirb ni
.reffo ot gnilliw saw eh laed a doog woh tuoba gnituohs
,rehtael fo shtgnel deggar emos ti morf decudorp dna
,deddon dna delkcuhc ilevuK ”.thginot tser ll’ew erehw uoy wohs ll’I ,nom’C“
.xof elttil eht ta nwod derats dna swaptoof sih ot ylneddus gnisir
,wap eno ni sevooh morf edam elttar a koohs ylhsirevef dna tsap deklaw eh sa
,yvaeh a htiw denruter dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,mih ta deffins ehs sa llits yrev deniamer ilevuK
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.akkeP sdrawot dednetxe neht eh hcihw
,oot sdnuos eht lla revo demmurd tI
.dnuow s’ilevuK ot gnidnet dehsinif eh sa kcab daeh sih dekcoc dna
,gnol s’akkeP hguorht wap sih nar dna dehgis arakaS ”.won dlo sretniw thgie
”?gnikniht uoy era tahW“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.mra sih gnittubdaeh yllufyalp erofeb
traeh sih no wap a tup eh sa dias eH
.rewsna s’rehtorb sih ta deddon neht ,deffuh ilevuK
.dooh niksreed eht fo edahs eht nihtiw demaeb elims thgirb a
.deprihc xof elttil ehT
”.dneirf ym ,uoy knahT“
.arakaS ,rehtorb ruoy wonk I“ ”?...uoy did woh“
,sesroh tuoba egnarts siht dnuof syawla dah ilevuK
”.dub elttil ,uoy llet I fi nuf on s’tI“
,akkeP rof gnitiaw
.elddim eht hguorht raeps a htiw
,rehtorb sih ta eugnot sih dekop eh sa edis sih ta dehcnelc tsif sih ,degnihw ilevuK ”?ti detrats I naem uoy od tahW“
,wap sih otni stunlezah deyenoh nezod a deruop eh
.swaptoof sih ta nwod derats eh sa
,delrang a tas hcihw nopu
,pu dekool ilevuK
netram ylredle ehT
,egarots otni ylefas kcab stunlezah eht tup eH
,ilevuK otni flesti denrub seye yklim sih ni degar taht onrefni ehT
.ti ecreip dluoc flow ylenol a fo lwoh eht neve toN
retlehs yreve dna hcae dnuora daeh sih dekop xof redlo ehT
.daeherof s’aneyh eht ta regnif ynwarcs ,gnol a detniop snomed fo royevrup eht
.etaf lufwa na ekil demees htob
,pollag ksirb a ot pu yaw reh krow akkeP tel dna
,tsrif-redluohs dednal eH
,deffuh ehs sa xof eht tsniaga dehcnelc hteet yepod reh
wap gnimriuqs eht tuo taps ilevuK
.tam rehtael eht no detegdif eh sa tuo sgel sih gnikcik ,deppay ilevuK ”!eep fo sknits tI“
,esaoc fo taoc taht woleb tsuj
.wodahs s’aneyh eht fo tuo kcab pets a gnikat ,shtaerb gnitnap
.nees reve d’eh enots neerg tseitterp eht fo eceip a ta yawa deliot ohw netram draggah a gnisuoh
.nur ot demaercs tug sih ni gnihtemos tub ,saw enots egnarts eht tahw ot sa suoiruc
.ihovatneL eht gnoma ekoj a emoceb dah ti tcaf nI
,yletilop daeh sih dewob ronoC
.dniw eht no revo detfaw ekomsdoow fo hcnets dirca eht hctac yltniaf dluoc eH
.xof elttil eht no denwad ti neht dnA
”-onk uoy evah ll’I ,nik ym si eH“
toN“	 .tnemeticxe s’gninrom taht fo hcum deppas dah yenruoj tew ,gnol eht
,ylper ni detrons akkeP dna dnuos kcilc a edam arakaS
”-hcrib a ekil ,yknal dna llat eb ot neppah t’ndluow rehtorb ruoY“
.dum kcils eht no pils ot ylno ,swaptoof sih ni-gid ot gniyrt
,esool xof elttil eht ekahs ot deirt netram eht sa lworg tnaifed a tuo tel eH
”?dlihc ,nik ruoy era erehW“
.deeps gninethgirf htiw devom netram eht ,ydob liarf sih etipseD
.senob wolley morf dekcah
.deraeppa dah ti sa ylkciuq sa tsuj
,lliks taerg htiw dekrow oot eh
.ssap emit eht pleh dluow krow eht
,yltnedifnoc detats rehtorb sih ”.won raf
”.oot emos evah yam uoy“
,ni yaw sti dnuof ylisae niaR
”!dum eb lliw erehT“
,duef rieht ot dnim yna yap ot ton demees dah
,srewolf ni derevoc
”.dub elttil ,reh def uoy fi erom ti etaicerppa d’ehs kniht I“ .hcuop gnilttar
”.roirraw ,yad eno dellik uoy teg lliw kram tahT“
.noitca otni deppans arakaS
,rehtorb redlo sih ot revo degdurt dna
.kaew snaem on yb ,aneyh nael
.pirg eltneg yldetcepxenu sih koot aneyh eht tub
”.xof ,oot uoy ees ot ecin s’tI“
,yas dluoc ilevuK lla saW ”.oot uoy ekil I“
,kool hsirevef a htiw ,deralg eH
.esae ot nageb mrots eht
.teem edart gniltsub eht sdrawot tort ot nageb ehs
,aneyh eht sa ruos denrut edit eht ,woN
sdooh rieht ta gnihsal niar eht
”.sega rof gnicitcarp neeb ev’ew ,wonk I“
”.tuo eugnot sih tuc tsomla I
.dooh sih nwod nar niar eht sa mih dniheb yltneg gnaws liat sih
?fo nekops dah arakaS dneirf eht siht saw
,stnecs eht lla yawa dehsaw tI
,uoy fo duorp m’I wonk uoY“
,eson sih dehcnip dna tuhs seye sih dezeeuqs xof elttil ehT
,mih detiawa taht egasuas reednier toh gnipip eht rof noitapicitna ni ylleb sih gnibbur
,edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc dna regnif ynob a desiar arakaS
,sdworc llams dnuora devaew arakaS
,ssarg yrd ni derevoc sretlehs dnuor elttil tuots
.dum gnikcus eht yb dewollaws gnieb morf stunlezah eht eucser ot degnul eh sa hsuls eht ni deppils eh
.sgniht rieht hguorht egammur ot nigeb
,esroh eht dednuor dna stunlezah fo hcuop eht dehctulc eH
.htlaeh sih retfa gniksa
,yaddim litnu nekat evah dluohs taht edir a os dnA
,kaolc sih nwod dum fo luftsif a deppord dah xof elttil eht taht ees ot nwod dekool arakaS
.sekorts wef a edih tfos s’esroh eht evag dna
retlehs sih ot kcab derepmacs dna revo dellor eh sa
”niaR gnirpS“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
,roolf eht gnola ekil yrrucs ot demees
sevael eht hguorht demaerts thgilnus mraw dna
.sderdnuh eb ot dah erehT
,yaw fo dnik gnizeehw a ni xof elttil eht deksA
,sdrawkcab delbmuts ilevuK
,rehtorb gib htiw emag gib tnuh ot
ekorb ecaf nrets sih tnemom feirb a rof dna ,pu decnalg ronoC ,nruter nI
.aneyh eht ot noitnetta sih denrut dna
.no gnivom yltfiws erofeb
noitseuq s’regnarts eht ta elbmert ot demees flesti ria ehT
kaolcniar s’ilevuK no gniggut yltneg ,dias eH
,defoorpretaw neeb dah niksreed ehT
,rennam ysaenu na ni deksa xof elttil ehT
.stroffe rieht tsniaga dekrow dah mrots eht niaga tub
.sretlehs fo ezam gnidniw eht deretne yeht sa evisavrep erom werg ylno llems ehT
.taorht liarf s’netram eht tsniaga desserp exa sih fo eldnah eht htiw pu gnittis
hcuop a otni dehcaer eh sa dnuow gnizoo eht ta decamirg eH
.redluohs eht no xof elttil eht gnittap
”.em htiw tserof eht hguorht reed gnikcart eb ll’uoy dna sretniw erom owT“
tleb sih ot nwod wap a dehcaer eh sa flesmih ot demmuh arakaS ”...akkeP ,yakO“
.flow yrros a ekil
akkeP dnuora morf droc edihwar a koot arakaS
lluks sih tsniaga talf gniog srae sih
,thgilnus eht ni enohs seye nworb krad riehT
.yerp rieht ot gninraw elttil evig ot
.elzzum s’esroh eht dnuora mra sih depparw dna nwod dehcuorc eh sa deredro eH
,hcuop eht denrutpu dna ylkaew delims xof elttil ehT
,sesnes s’xof elttil eht ypucco ot esle gnihton saw erehT
.rof deretrab eb ot yleerf gnuh taht emag derehctub ylhserf eht morf htaed dna
enips s’xof elttil eht pu revihs a gnidnes
,llat a erew yehT
,guh mraw a ni ilevuK decarbme eH
sdrawno depollag yeht sa thgis eht ot dnim on diap rehtorb siH
,tnilf ta yawa gnippihc sretnuh fo lufwap a
,eromyna ti detrats ohw rettam t’nseod tI“
.esimorpmoc eht ta deveiler ylraelc ,delahxe arakaS
,niaga xof elttil eht ta pu delims eh sa dedda eH
.netram ylredle eht tsniaga dehsarc dna
.htrae denruhc eht revo deeps gniksir
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.gnildduc eht no ni ronoC tel ot gnireffo ,demaeb eH
,delggig ilevuK ”.uoy sekil eH“
raeb eht ot pu deppets regnarts
.rae denettalf a dniheb dehctarcs eh sa
.roolf eht ot pord ti tel dna hcuop eht fo og tel eh
llih llams a fo timmus eht gnihcaer
,ti fo thguoht eht ta etavilas tub pleh t’ndluoc ilevuK
,daeh sih revo eseeg fo riap a dleh xof yarg enO
,delahxe aneyh ehT
.ti detcepsni dna trid fo pmulc eht dehctans eh erofeb ylmrif eson s’akkeP gnibbur
”.sregnif gnivomer trats ot deen t’now I dna og yob eht teL“
.rehtorb sih sdrawot hsup elttil a ilevuK gnivig
,tsehc s’xof elttil eht otni eson reh dehsup akkeP .elzzum tneitapmi na yb detpurretni saw eh ,rehtorb sih knaht ot sdrow eht rof dehcraes ilevuK sA
.triks edih krowhctap sih fo trohs tsuj deppots dna sgniggel s’xof elttil eht fo mottob eht dekac taht
tuat dellup gnieb elzzum sih no ruf eht
,krow fo erac nekat evah I retfa ,worromoT …yakO“
.ti fo ecart yna nword ot tsrow sti gniod niar eht
,enob eht ot gnulc llits hselF
”.yrruh t’nod ew fi yad eht rof dehsinif evah lliw teem eht ,nom’C“ .ilevuK ot denrut neht
.ylregae gnikcilf liat sih
.xof gnuoy eht ot esolc oot elttil a gniyarts wap sih
dum fo rettaps dna
”.enola dna tsol lla ,yob diputS“
evah ot demees retlehs rehto yrevE
,yalpsid detareggaxe na no tup eh sa gnikrims ,deggeb arakaS
.ecaf s’rehtorb sih no elims daorb a ees ot
,oot dehctaw dah ilevuK
.dne sti tem dah kle eht woh fo kniht ot dedaerd ilevuK
.yzzid leef xof elttil eht edam ti taht sseltneler os
.nwod dehcuot eh tnemom eht
deksa eH ”?uoy llet ton rehtorb ruoy diD
”.niaga mih ees ot detnaw I dna ,dnik yrev saw nosrep siht tub ,ebyaM“
”.rehtorb ym htiw m’I dna ,ilevuK si eman yM“
hsif deird dna sniks reednier ydruts morF
.elims yhtoot ,drawkwa na rehtorb elttil sih dereffo dna revo dehcnuh xof rellat ehT
,taerg a hctaw ot
.retniw eht fo dne eht sdrawot raet ot nugeb dah smaes eht tub
.gnol rof ytisoiruc hsidlihc sih tsiser t’ndluoc ilevuK elttil sa
.mrots hguoroht a retfa emac syawla taht rodo pmad
,esnet ydob s’netram ylredle eht tlef ilevuK dna
,ylduorp detats arakaS
,syad eseht fo eno yrots lluf a ikahK dnes dluohs yllaer ohw ,xoFarakaS yb
.yaw eht fo tuo gnippets
hself yrehtael dna ruf ekil-wenis eht gnicreip
.sregnif sih htiw gnilddif ,yldi dum eht dekcik eH
,sretlehs eht hguorht esor ti sa liart ekil-tnepres
.doog on saw ti tub ,ezag gnicreip sih fo eri gnillihc eht dna
redluohs sih dniheb thgiew sih tsurht aneyh eht sa spetswap fo mrots a saw erehT
.ssem a gnikam dna htrae eht fo tuo ssarg fo stfut nworb gnippir daetsni
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,xoFarakaS yb
.xof gnuoy eht no detaxif seye yklim ,neknus siH
,dekrow eh sa hteet wolley sih tirg netram dlo ehT
,gnivaeh eht dewollof yehT .redwop
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”.oot dab sllems ,haeY ?eert hcrib A“
”.rekamelbuort elttil eht eucser ot tif was I
kcab deraeppasid neht
,dum eht fo tuo flesmih deluah dna ti koot ilevuK
.swap htob ni exa tnilf a gnihctulc
,rehtorb yracs ’n gib ruoy m’I“
eye na fo egami eht demrof taht yalc der debuad-ylhserf eht ta
.enord gnittilps-rae ,tnatsnoc a
.flesmih decudortni syawla dah rehtorb sih woh saw tI
.elbatrofmocnu ylgnisaercni leef ot htaeneb niks eht dna ,yllufniap kcits ot ruf sih desuac hcihw
.edalb neddih a htaehsnu thgim eno ekil
,delrans aneyh ehT
,revir eht fo sretaw nworb
”.etal ydaerla er’ew dna hguorht edir ot ysub oot s’ti ,nom’C“
,egnarts taht saw ereht dnA
.llaf tsal hcorua yb ffilc a revo desahc saw eH
.retlehs yreve dna hcae ni yawa gnikrow redart yreve dna hcae ta reep ot nageb xof elttil eht os dna
,ylikeehc kcab delims xof elttil ehT
ecaf sih fo tuo eson s’arakaS gnihsup ylmrif
,eram yarg-elppad rieht ,akkeP
,ria eht dekohc taht amsaim a saw tI
,enips sih otni dekop taht netram eht fo emarf ynob eht neewteb thguac ilevuK elttil
.ylthgils dedaf elims sih
,erolpxe ot erutan gnuoy sih ni saw tI
.teem edart eht dnuora tsim niht a ni gnirehtag
,radnelaC pU-niP syaD noitacaV
.daeh eht no ilevuK gnittap ,dedda eH
eye na fo knilb eht ni egnahc dluow seye enilef woh fo
.wap dehctertstuo s’xof elttil eht hcaer ot daeh reh rewol ylwols ot dah akkeP
ydob s’ilevuK hguorht dehsarc niaP
.wap rehto sih htiw llems eht gnitfaw
,gnidir hguor fo hcterts rehtona retfA
.noitale fo esnes mraw a htiw ilevuK gnillif
,retlehs eht sdrawot pets ot nageb ilevuK
,kaolc niksreed dedooh sih htaenrednu morf tuo mra na deppils arakaS
,ereh rekciht neve wohemos saw dum ehT
,mra s’xof eht morf swalc sih detcartxe dna pirg sih denesool eH
,neppah dluow siht wonk ot dah rehtorb gib siH
.tuo traeh sih gnas
.tsehc sih nwod elkcirt noitasnes tew
”?yltcaxe ,tahw rof etaL“
.slirtson s’ilevuK nrub ot werg ekomsdoow fo hcnets eht dna
.elzzum sih fo egde eht otno tperc gnivah elims eltbus a
kle daed a neve dna seert elohw sa dekcohs
,edis eht no esroh eht dettap arakaS
.teef sih ta derats eh sa talf tnew srae sih ,dehgis ilevuK
,detnemmoc aneyh ehT ”.seiceps ruoy erahs neve t’nseod
,revewoh ,tsal ton dluow kcul siH
.gniklus ,niar eht ni doots eh sa
.meht dnuora detrap tserof eht sa tlah a ot deddiks dna
.rehtorb sih gniwollof
.yad gnitsuahxe na hcus retfa swen doog dedeen hcum emos
.erofeb rehtegot elpoep ynam os nees reven d’eh tub
.ekila nevar dna ,hcorua
.esroh rieht ffo nwod derebmalc xof rellams eht sa thgiew s’rehtorb elttil sih gnikat
.dum eht hguorht no degdurt dna denrut xof elttil eht os dna
,kcals sredluohs dna edis sih ta smra ,seye gnidaelp
”niaR gnirpS“ saw sihT
.dnuow eht dnuora ylthgit depparw eh hcihw
.htolcniol nikserah dna
.stoob rieht ta deggans sbmil enip gnignah-wol sa
,secaf rieht ni dniw eht htiw
seninac derruf-etihw tsegnarts eht htiw staobniks revo deretrab yeht sa uvval rieht yb doots ,sesroh rieht htiw ihovatneL wollef was eH
.dum ni dekac wap a dna
god laref a ekil delworg netram ehT
sdaehworra tnilf fo snezod ot
.daeh sih dekcilf dna ilevuK ot dekool neht eH
daeh reh kcub ot eram yarg-elppad eht desuac dna
,ylteiuq dias arakaS
?flesmih ot meht tpek rehtorb sih daH
”…pmac remmus eht ot teg ew nehw
,gnimlehwrevo saw hcnets ehT
.edis s’akkeP ot dnuora kcab gniggoj-flah ,deddon xof elttil ehT
niaga ihovatneL eht htiw eb ot degnol eH .nuf os demees tI
tsav a deyarteb taht kool a htiw gnitiaw dna gnihctaw syawla tub ,elines tib a spahrep
,thginot dnetta ot gnihtemos evah I diarfa m’I“
.retlehs derevoc-ssarg eht ot kcab flesmih gniggard nigeb dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,noitca otni depmuj ilevuK
tort a ta detrats yehT
.hgis a tuo gnittel dna
elddas rieht sa detca taht teknalb ruf eht revo gel sih detfil dna
.noos gniog teg t’ndid yeht fi wollof ot erus saw hguoc ytsan A .sehtolc dekaos sih ecreip ot nugeb dah niar ehT
.rethgit dna rethgit depparw saw rehtael eht sa gnihcnilf
.meht nopu detniap serutaerc denroh-xis ,llat fo segami
,ti eveileb t’nac llits I“
tneler netram eht ees ot deveiler saw eh
.stunlezah deyenoh fo tuo nur d’yeht thguoht eh
,gnol neewteb deffuh xof ehT
.seert eht ni hgih esuorg fo letrohc reppihc eht dna
,deksa dna aneyh eht ta daeh sih dekcoc eH
.pleh s’rehtorb sih htiw dum eht otni yllufecarg deppord eh sa edis eno ot yltneg gnitnals daeh sih
sgniggel edihesroh sih pu dum dehsalps dna
htarw s’mrots eht fo tsrow ehT	 .enam gnilkraps
snomed fo royevrup siht morf yawa teg ot dah eh
ehT	 .kcab sih nwod deppird ti sa
.ekoms dna dum gnitacoffus fo ettelap mirg eht gnoma
.uoy tuoba gniklat pots t’ndluow rehtorb ruoY“
.nikrej s’aneyh eht otni ecaf sih gnicrof xof elttil eht
.mra s’ilevuK dezies dna tuo dehcaer eh sa
.nomed fo dnik emos neeb evah ylno dluoc tI
,evah uoy nik ecreif emoS“
,lautir egnarts a saw tI
,htaeneb neddih rewop eht leef dluoc eH
epoh fo evaw laitini eht ,deplug ilevuK
”.rennid rof segasuas reednier wef a dna ,thginot yats ot erehwemos su dnuof I“
,pmad reh delffur dna
llams a fo mrof eht ni seitisoiruc txen eht dnuof xof elttil
.rehto hcae tsniaga
,smra sih dedlof ilevuK
.deeps gninethgirf htiw
.niaga dekcilf liat ekil-hsurb ,egnarts siH
.wef a eman ot tsuj ,snetram ehtil dna sraeb gnikluh
.esroh rieht ffo deppils dna
.ecalp eno ni sevlesmeht eveiler ot gnideen lla sretnuh derdnuh a fo tluser eht saw demussa xof elttil eht hcihw
ehT	 .erujnoc dluoc ecalp siht ytisoiruc txen eht rof gnikool
,ruf s’rehtorb sih ot gnulc xof elttil ehT
revir nellows eht fo raor eht yb decalper
.ezeerb eltneg a ni pans dluow yeht hguoht sa dekool taht sbmil ynob no tas ,tneicna saw netram eht
,dloc a tlef dna talps tfos a draeh arakaS litnu ,saw tahT
.rehtorb redlo sih wollof ot ilevuK degru dna drawrof deppets eh sa
sevael gnirps gnuoy eht no niar thgil fo rettap eltneg eht ylno saw ereht won dna ,gninrom taht dessap dah
.aneyh mulg eht fo thgis eht ta dedaf elims sih
.elffins suodnemert a htiw eson sih morf sucum ynnur bur ot mra sih gnisu
”?teem siht si rehtruf hcum
sexnyl yttops erew erehT
.laedi neeb evah dluow ti
,sloot fo sdnik lla otni senots hguor eht dekrow yehT
,esroh tnatiseh rieht htiw deniagrab rehtorb gib sih
.liart eht nwod drawno akkeP redro ot sgel sih fo sezeeuqs eltbus desu arakaS
,retrohs eb dluow yenruoj eht denokcer dah rehtorb siH
.daeh s’xof elttil eht sa gib sa saw edalb ehT
dekrab xof elttil ehT ”!eduR“
.yab ta moderob eht peek ot ,erif eht yb seirots gnillet elihw edam d’yeht
,dehcaorppa yeht sa sexof owt eht teerg ot daeh reh desiar ehs dna
.ezis reh flah ylno xof elttil eht dna stunlezah eht morf yawa ,kcab reh dehsup eH
.erom ton fi ,sretnuh net fo rewop eht dessessop ydob taht tub
,eltsihw gnicreip a tuo tel rehtorb gib sih sa srae sih derevoc ilevuK
,detneler arakaS ,tnemom a retfA
.thgilnus eht ni gninihs ruf yarg yrevlis
.seno tnenimorp tsom eht tsuj saw taht dnA
,detneler aneyh ehT ”.uoy htiw emit emos dneps lliw I
.xof eht erutpacer ot evom yna edam eh fi ekirts ot ydaer dna
.yerf eht otni tsrif-daeh
,dum eht otni gnilwarps tnes erew meht fo eerht ehT
,swaptoof sih ot esor
”.nrobbuts gnieb spots akkeP sa gnol sa tsuJ“
drawrof gnippets erofeb noitcerid niatrec a ni daeh sih dekcilf arakaS
sgnul gnivaeh eht
dum eht otni mih gnihsup tsomla
,ilevuK diaS ”.gniod er’uoy tahw wonk ot mees uoY“
ytisoiruc ekil-lamina na htiw decalper gnieb seye sih ni eri eht
.yas ot gniog saw aneyh eht tahw yltcaxe gniwonk
,kcen s’esroh eht dettap arakaS
.dum eht fo tuo flesmih detfil ylismulc eh sa
xof elttil eht nopu tpael evah dluow eh hguoht sa dekool xof redlo eht
,hcnets eliv a dah revir eht nevE
.enot sih ot gnimmuh tfos a
.dekcut liat dna kcab dennip srae sih
.ytiniffAruF no
.sregnif kcarc ylbaborp dluoc hteet esoht dna
.wap lufpleh a gnidnetxe
reehc desserppus htiw deredro eH ”.niaga elbuort ni teg uoy erofeb ,no oG“
.kcuht tew ,tfos a htiw dednal arakaS hsalps a fo daetsni dna
,xof elttil eht dnuora rethgit depparw smra sih
,ylreporp denaelc neeb ton gnivah ylraelc
,edarahc gums eht ekorb arakaS ,yllautnevE
,rehtorb elttil sih ta yllufyalp delworg eH
,erats tub pleh t’ndluoc ilevuK
.ssendnik fo sraey esoht lla rof kcab evig dna
,pil sih tib netram ehT
enips sih pu toohs raef fo tloj a tlef xof elttil ehT
,desiar worbeye na
”?elbuort yob siht gnisuac uoy erA“ ”!rehtorb giB“
,retlehs derevoc-ssarg
.krims suoveihcsim a gnihsalf
”.mih ot dednet dna dnuof I
.naidisbo neve ro ,etals
.gniraelc tsav eht thgis eht ta deppord waj siH
,erac taerg htiw niks eht revo edalb tnilf eht dekrow raeb citnagig ehT
.derutseg dah rehtorb sih noitcerid eht ni decnalg dna
.hctiwt ot nageb eson s’ilevuK
,ffits tnew xof elttil ehT
.ronoC morf lworg detraeh-flah a deticile ylno ssenesolc ehT
,retlehs eht deduorhs taht seigiffe dna smrahc eht saw ti spahreP
”.thgirhtrib ym si uoy ot edur gnieb
”.pmac remmus eht ta tseug ruo sa uoy tsoh su tel tsael ta ,esaelP“
.repeed gud swalc eht sa
dekrep srae ,pu tas ilevuK
.ffurcs eht ni ecaf sih gniyrub dna
.edis sih ta nwod dehcuorc dna rehtorb elttil sih ot revo delffuhs eh
,level s’ilevuK ot nwod dehcuorc regnarts ehT
,sregdab depirts dna
.hcamots sih dnuora depparw mra na htiw dehgual dna doots arakaS
tsiaw s’xof redlo eht ot flesmih gnihctal
hself tneluccus fo eceip yreve ta gniloord morf peek ot deganam ilevuK neve dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,kcab derats arakaS
.sredda fo ned a fo monev eht lla htiw aneyh eht ta gnilwocs
,deddon dna ilevuK ot denrut eH
sknab rieht wollaws ot srevir gnilior eht desuac dna
selcsum gnorts fo eniltuo esnet eht ees dluoc ilevuK
.slliks sih fo tsaob dna sretnuh rehto eht htiw gnittahc sthgin dneps ot
,hsiuqs llud a htiw dednal
.enam demoorg ylluferac
,nworc reltna na htiw namahs a sa dehctaw eH
”.uoy ot txen gnipeels ekil s’ti tahw wonk uoy won ,lleW“
.nialpxe ot gniunitnoc
,ylteiuq delkcuhc arakaS ”?won dnuof uoy ev’tahw ,lrig ylliS“
.gag a sserppus ot htuom sih derevoc xof elttil eht dna
,tnatsni na ni dehsinav ezag dliw s’netram enip ehT
.ruf dettops-kcalb ekil-dnas
edis eht ot daeh sih dekcoc ilevuK
”.uoy ni kcab ygrene emos tog ev’uoy tsael tA“
,sredle esiw ekil erom erew sesroH
,delggurts dna demriuqs ilevuK
.nworb ybburg a deniats ruf etihw dehsawnu sih
.elzzum sih ssorca dehcterts krims yls a ,eson sih pu denrut dna
,akkeP otno gnidloh rof t’nsaw ti fI
tsaeb detooferus a saw ehs rof ,deirrow ton saw arakaS
.stirips tserof suoirav fo seman railimaf wef a ediseb sdrow ynam dnatsrednu t’ndluoc eH
,netram ylredle eht no ylelos dexif
,gniticxe thguoht eht dnuof llits eH
namahs eht ta nwod gnireep
:sdnik lla fo sretlehs htiw dekcap saw tI
.esu elttil fo eb ot devorp ti hguoht ,daeh sih dnuora rethgit dooh nwo sih dellup ilevuK
,ssim ot kramdnal drah a saw ti
,ecnatsid efas a morf dehctaw ilevuK
woH“	 .tes ot gninnigeb saw nus eht litnu dehcterts dah
.kcen eht yb gnola xof ynit ylevitaler eht gniggard
retniw dlim a hcus
s’evitarepooC ediseriF eht ot krow detubirtnoc yltnecer sah dna
.sgnul sih morf ria eht dehsurc taht aneyh eht fo klub eht dna
aneyh eht ,gnirats drawkwa fo tnemom a retfA
.stirips revir eht kcirt ot ruf rieht otni redneval debbur ihovatneL eht nehw