nalA taht desseug htieK
,ssalc eht fo pot eht ta smeti gnipeekesuoh wef a fo erac koot nalA
,spil s’htieK tsniaga eugnot sih dils dna
,mih ot emas eht did htieK elihw ,trihs sih nottubnu ot detrats dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta
.rood moorhtab eht fo kcab eht no kooh eht no ,dednah-eno ,ti gnah ot deganam dna
,xofnogarD nelarD yb
.taorht sih deraelc nalA
.t’ndluohs I taht yradnuob a gnikaerb em naht retteb si doom eht gnikaerB .sgniht gnippots tuoba dab leef ton od on ,esaelp ,oN“
pitregnif sih dils nalA
daeh s’htieK fo kcab eht deppuc eH
,deilper dna rediw dennirg nalA
.erovinrac a saw eh dnA
?yltnatcepxE ?ylsuovreN
,sdraob eht ta emit sih fo tsom tneps eH
mih fo tnorf ni ksed eht no koobeton sih tup eH
,gniknird neeb dah nalA yeksihw eht etsat dluoc eH
.lla ta gnihtyna em ewo uoy naem t’nseod knird a uoy thguob dna
.ssalc tsrif sih ot yawllah eht gniklaw suovren elttil a tlef eh
,dehgual nalA  ”?stohS“
.ytisrevinU ta raey tsrif sih ni dna loohcs hgih ni kcaB
.rab eht ot pu yltnedifnoc gniklaw htieK ees ot dnuora denrut nalA  ”.semoc ti ereh
”.hguoht ,elbuort dooG
S“ .elttil a gnitnap llits osla saw eH
.yltneg ,kcab sih nwod dna pu dnah sih dils dna
.mih ediug lamina reggib eht gnittel
,raf oot gnihtyna ekat I fi
,niaga htieK ta dekool eH
.htieK ot nwod denael nalA
.niaga s’htieK ot spil sih desserp eh dna
,puorg eht fo egde eht dnuora gnirevoh htieK ees dluoc nalA
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.era uoy erehw neeb ev’I
.xim eht otni sdrow nwo sih fo emos worht ot detnaw dna
,yltcaxe rednetrab eht wonk uoy od llew woh …oS“
.gninrom txen eht pu mih ekow enohp s’htieK
.tsehc sih ni lworg wol a evag dna
.keehc s’htieK gnola sregnif sih fo kcab eht nur yltneg ot dnah rehto sih detfil dna
.flesmih ta nwod dekool dna
,mih hguorht thgir nees dah ohw enoemos saw ereh won dna
.kcen s’htieK fo senil eht nwod yltfos spitregnif sih gnicart ,tnemom a retfa kcab dellup eH
,dnoces a rof ssik eht fo tuo dellup nalA
,niaga tsehc s’nalA ta dessik yltneg eH
.ffo eit sih gut ot detrats htieK sa niaga yltfos delworg eH
”.setunim owt ni era smoorhsaw eht erehw em nioJ“
,yltfos derepsihw dna rae s’nalA ot ni denael eH
.yaw taht leef ot uoy tnaw t’nod yletinifed I
”.tuo dnif ot detseretni m’I tuB
.shgiht s’htieK ot nwod detfird swap gib sih dna
.thgin tsal rewohs a ekat ot ypeels oot tlef t’ndah eh dehsiw eh tub
taeh eht tlef eh woN !slrig dnA
tsehc s’htieK revo nar sdnah daorb gib s’nalA dna ,nepo erew strihs rieht fo htob ,nooS
.keehc s’noil eht no ssik eltneg a ecalp ot pu denael dna
.tsehc s’noil eht tsniaga yltneg delzzun dna drawrof daeh sih denael eH
.tey tuo ton …s’eH“
”.sruoh eciffo ym era ereh
,tceted dluoc eh taht revognah oN
,yltfos dias nalA dna ,dehgual htob yehT
tel reven dah eH
.flesmih revo lla nalA llems llits dluoc eH
”.rood eht kcol uoy erus ekam dna ,moorhsaw eeyolpme eht esu tsuJ
.drac a htieK dednah dna dennirg nalA
,tsiser t’ndid htieK dna
.rosseforp noil wen siH
.llew wonk ydaerla t’ndid eh taht serovinrac gib dnuora suovren elttil a neeb syawla dah htieK
,seye evisserpxe gib esoht otni
s’amall eht htiw elbmuf ot detrats dna
”.emit gnol a ni tem ev’I nosrep wen gnitseretni tsom eht er’uoy ,sediseB
.htieK ta demaeb hanoJ
saw eh wonk mih tel taht naom teiuq a yb deinapmocca
elttil a kcab sih dehcra eH
.ruf tfos ,kciht s’noil eht ni delgnat
.hcuot ni yats nac ew os rebmun ruoy em evig ll’uoy epoh I
.eson sih hguorht detnap nalA
.tuo gnihcaer saw dna
,delworg dna yllufyalp delwocs nalA
,tuo denniht ti sa deyats dna
,dias dna taorht sih deraelc neht
.3OA no noitcifnaf )sratsaeB yltsom( sih dnif nac uoY
.noitarepo eritne eht rof detrap ylerab spil riehT
.smoor kcab ni serovinrac htiw pu gnikooh
.esnopser ni dennirg htieK
.meht desserdda eh dna ,pu tohs sdnah wef A  ”?snoitseuq ynA“
.kcab sih pu nar taht llirht eht tsiser t’ndluoc eh tub ,suovren tlef eH
,xofnogarD nelarD yb ”riA hserF fo htaerB a rof tuO gnippetS“
,suovren ylsuoivbo saw amall ehT
,tsehc nwo sih nwod sregnif sih nar dna
,ylleb dna tsehc sih revo loow tfos kciht lufituaeb eht
.llaw eht tsniaga amall eht gnisserp
.sehtolc dna ruf s’noil eht morf setteragic fo tnecs eht llems dluoc eh dna
”.drawkwa si siht ,lleW“
”?yako ,won hcuot ni yatS“
.rab eht no nwod ssalg tohs eht tup eh sa ecno dehguoc dna
,knird sih fo pis rehtona koot dna ,elttil a delkcuhc htieK
?sliatkcoc fo elpuoc a revo delaever eb lliw esle tahW
.htieK ,uoy gniteem erusaelp ym neeb sah tI
,swalc sih fo luferac eb ot tseb sih gniyrt ,rethgit redluohs s’htieK deppirg eH
.yawyna recnuob a eb ot hguone em yap t’nod yehT
.flesmih ot yltfos dias eh
.saw eh naht rellat mees mih edam dliub mils sih tub ,llat t’nsaw eH
.etavirp saw ti wenk eh esuaceb elbat siht dekcip eH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.raf oot saw taht …yrros-
.keehc s’htieK gnola spitregnif sih ekorts yltfos ot pu dnah sih thguorb dna deffuh nalA
s’amall eht ot spil sih desserp dna
ylleb yffulf s’noil eht hguorht sregnif sih gnidils yb dednopser eh dna
.sknird rieht koot dna sessalg deknilc noil dna amall yehT  ”.ton yhw ,eruS“
.emit eht dekcehc dna enohp sih tuo dellup htieK
htieK rof rood eht denepo neht
?moor kcab eht oT .seY ?rab eht oT“
.ti fo enon gnivah saw htieK tuB
,deddon dna ,seye s’nalA otni peed dekool htieK  ”?yako
.nalA ta dennirg hanoJ
,kcen mils sih fo evruc eht gnola dna
.thgir gnihtemos gniod
sdnah s’nalA tlef eH
.ssik eht otni kcab mih deggut dna eit s’nalA debbarg eH
,lamina rellams eht ta nwod kool ot elttil a kcab dellup nalA
.htieK ta nwod ylitfarc dennirg nalA
.gnippoh erew ew ,thgin tsal ereh mih gnirb t’ndid uoy gniht dooG
”.emoh gnitteg eb ot deen yllaer I
,rewohs eht ni llew flesmih debburcs dah eH
.yllausac tub ,ylprahs desserd saw eH .oot
.regnarts gniugirtni na htiw noitasrevnoc gnitseretni yrev a ni pu dedne dna
”?laiceps os em sekam tahw oS“
.gnikool yllaer ton tub
mih gnillet saw ydob sih emit emas eht ta elihw eelf ot mih gnillet stcnitsni sih fo gnileef eht morf gnileer saw eH
”…rof ydaer m’I fi wonk t’nod I …tub
,daeh s’nalA fo kcab eht ta enam kciht eht ni pu sregnif sih parw ot pu dehcaer eH
,reganeet suoilleber a ekil tib a tlef llits eH
nalA ot pu deklaw eH
.sgniht ynam os dias sdrow owt esohT
.ffuts renehserf ria eht yarps tsuj ll’I“
.emarf mils dna ehtil sih
.hteet suoiciv dna prahs gnidih
.od ot tuoba saw noil eht tahw tuoba suoiruc yleniuneg tub
.gnihtyna tpurretni t’ndluow hanoJ wenk eh dna
S“ ,dias dna ,gnitnap llits
”.syad wef a rof ereht kcab amall ekil llems thgim ti hguohT .gnihton
.elihw a rof mih dael erovinrac gib siht tel oT
.eerf erom tlef reven dah htieK
.rab eht no denael dna pu deklaw htieK
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.esarhp taht etah I woh ,hgU“
,noil fo gniknits yletulosba siht fo tuo emoc d’eh dezilaer htieK
,snortap rehto eht fo enon tub
.sessalc gninrom sih rof ydaer teg ot deb fo tuo flesmih deggard dna semit fo elpuoc a spil sih dekcams eH
.yldnik mih ta gnilims saw ohw nalA ta pu dekool eH
,rab eht fo tuo deklaw eh sa gnilims saw htieK
.amall eht ta kool retteb a teg ot tnemom a koot noil ehT
.mih desaet htieK sa hteet
.delims dna ,gnitnap llits ,nalA ta pu dekool htieK
,gnillirht saw taht kcab sih nwod elgnit a tnes tI
.hcuot s’nalA otni elttil a denael neht
”.rab eht fo kcab eht ni erovibreh rellams a htiw tuo gnikam erovinrac gib a fo scitpo eht rof elbuort ni uoy teg ot tnaw t’nod ,oslA .lla si teercsid siht peek ot yrt ot gnioG
,lairetam eht htiw pleh emos deen reve uoy fi ,lleW“
,ereh saw eh taht woN
.serovibreh neeb lla d’yeht tuB
.ssalc ,gninrom dooG“
.sedapacse rieht gnirud nrot neeb dah gnihton ,ylippaH
.ecaf railimaf a saw
.seye s’noil eht otni gnirats
.tey ,nalA morf kcab raeh ot gnitcepxe t’nsaw eh
”.did tsuj uoy tahw od ot neht ecnedifnoc eht dah d’I hsiw I
”,em gniddik eb ot tog evah uoY“
”.taht tuoba yrros-
,ssik eht otni ylteiuq delworg nalA
htaerb peed a koot htieK
.ssik eltneg a rof
.nalA nihtiw gninekawa ylniatrec saw gnihtemos tub
.siht gniod saw eh eveileb ylerab dluoc eH
,elbuort fo gnikaeps tuB
.ti devol eh ,denmad eb stcnitsnI .citoxe
,pal sih otni nwod dekool htieK
”?uoy did ,ereht kcab pu naelc ot em rof ssem a evael t’ndid uoY“
.hcuot eltneg s’noil eht otni keehc sih denael eH
.flesmih gnicudortni detrats dna
,depleh kcen mils ,gnol ehT
tsiaw s’htieK ot pu sdnah sih dils eH
”.tsael ta sdneirf sA
”.noos uoy ees ot epoH .hanoJ ,oot uoY
.knis eht revo flehs a otno eit sih gnissot
,yad eht fo ssalc tsrif sih deretne eH
”.yawyna esruoc siht no erutcel gnineve eht ot evom ot dennalp dah I taht wonk uoy tel ot detnaw I ,yawynA
?neht ,dael eht ekat em tel uoy t’nod yhw ,lleW“
.kcab deppets eh dna
.thginot teiuq repus s’ti ,erus naem I“
.dehgis dna nihc sih rednu enam s’nalA hguorht sregnif sih delffur eH
”.em gniddik eb ot tog ev’uoY“
-saw eh naht redlo sraey net tuoba ylbaborp saw
.tey ,wonk t’nod I“
,selbatemit maxe tuoba noitseuq a dah regit a erehw edis eht ot ffo dekool eH
,ylsuoituac denrut neht dna
,deksa dna nobruob fo elttob a pu dleh eH
,rab a ta dneirf sih yb dehctid tlef htieK ,emit tsaL
,ytterp os saw amall ehT
.rab eht ot denruter yeht dna
,dnoces a rof rab eht ta nwod dekool dna delkcuhc nalA
,no kcab ti deppils dna
nihc s’htieK rednu
”?ti saw hanoJ ,mu ,knird a fo lleh a xim uoY“
.won thgir reganeet a sa suovren sa tuoba tlef eh ,timda ot dah eH
.liatkcoc a barg ot gniog fo gnikniht m’I
.forp wen rieht rof snoitseuq tsal emos htiw tnorf eht ot pu emac stneduts wef a
ruf tfos ,mraw eht dessik eH
.nwo sih htiw gnicnad yllufyalp eugnot s’erovibreh eht htiw dedrawer saw dna
,mih wollof ot htieK detivni dna taorht sih
.ffo mih tuc nalA
.sikahk lausac otni dekcut trihs sserd letsap neerg nialp A
,sehtolc fo tes hserf a dna rewohs a retfa nevE
.seno cilbup eht gnitacidni srood owt eht dniheb moorhtab ffats eht sdrawot mih del dna
.deggurhs htieK dna
.deb ni pu tas dna elttil a denaorg eH
tsehc s’htieK pu sdnah sih dils noil ehT
.tsehc s’nalA no yltneg dnah sih tup dna drawrof pets a koot eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,rab eht ta hanoJ ees dluoc eH
,moor eht fo tuo delif enoyreve dna dedne ssalc sA
,emarf ralucsum sih tsniaga resolc mih llup dna kcab sih nwod edils
,oN“ .dehgual nalA
,ezorf sdnah s’nalA  ”…tiaw ,on …tiaw-
.elbuort ekil smees eno sihT“
.gnihtyna ro ecilam eduxe t’ndid ylniatrec nalA tuB
,stcnitsni yrotaderp neeb evah ton yam tI
,seye sih desolc nalA
.tniop siht ta gnirac tsap llew saw eh tub
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.ti dekil uoy dalG !em s’tahT“
,lleW“  ”?won tahw oS“
.mih htiw gnitrilf neeb neve evah yam
”riA hserF fo htaerB a rof tuO gnippetS“
,flesmih ot thguoht eh sa taorht sih deraelc nalA
on em llet ot deen tsuj uoY
.keehc sih tsniaga edils ti tel dna
.elppin sih dnuora hteet erovibreh fo erusserp eltneg eht ta hteet sih hguorht dessih dna
.desserd dna tuo denethgiarts teg ot tseb rieht did dna srebmun degnahcxe slamina owt ehT
,htieK ta nwod kcab dekool eH
”?ecalp siht ni moor kcab a ereht si dna
,sdnah gib sih fo eno ni
.elttil a dehgual htieK
.rosseforp wen sih ta pu dekool dna
.yawa sessalg eht deraelc hanoJ
,tuhs rood eht dellup dna thgil eht no dekcilf eH
”.oga emit gnol a saw tI“
.erutcel sih otni devled neht dna
”.emit gnol gnol a ni tem ev’I lamina gnitseretni tsom eht yletinifed era uoY .egami ym tuoba deirrow ton m’I ,on tuB“
tekcaj tius sih fo tekcop edisni eht otni eit sih deffuts nalA
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,ni deklaw rosseforp eht nehw tuo koobeton sih gnitteg deipucco saw eH
,nepo gnignah saw trihs sih dna delffur saw loow siH
”.tniop eros a saw ti wonk t’ndid I ,yrroS !yrroS“
.tsaf gnitaeb traeh sih
.ylkciuq moor eht dennacs nalA
.pu sdnah sih tup htieK
,erofeb syug htiw trilf ot yrt ot hguone evarb tlef t’ndah eH
.lortnoc ni ton s’eh ekil leef ot tnemom a tsuj roF
.nalA ,thgin doog a evaH .oot eM“
,ylleb s’nalA fo ffulf kciht eht tsniaga tsehc sih desserp eH
,on tub ,sknahT .etal s’tI .foO“
I“ .rehtegot sdnah sih dedlof dna
,htieK ot resolc elttil a deldis nalA
.llah erutcel eguh eht ni enola erew yeht litnu
,s’htieK ot spil sih sserp ot niaga ni denael eH
.dne ym no elbuort on
”?netfo ereh syug gnirb uoY“
,heM“ .deggurhs hanoJ
tsehc sih tsniaga desserp emarf thgils sih gnileef
.noitasnes suoiruxul a saw tI
.gniliugeb saw noisserpxe ehT
.dehgual htieK dna ,worbeye na dekcoc nalA
”?owt uoy rof knird rehtonA
.lworg taht htiw niaga ecno derevihs htieK
.uoy fo esuaceb toN“
sih dehcnelc nalA  .elbbin eltneg a ti evag htieK sa naom a yb dewollof
,tuo emac shturt emoS
,enam s’nalA ni sregnif sih elgnat yltneg ot
spil tfos ,mraw esoht dna ,mih tsniaga desserp noil siht fo htgnerts dna
,ssalc eht ni gnirevoc eb dluow yeht lairetam eht fo sekorts daorb eht tuo dial d’eh retfA
.lworg taht fo dnuos eht morf pu dnats kcen sih fo kcab eht no ruf eht tlef htieK
.taes rieht ni tuo edam yltneg dna yltfos yeht sa
.hguorht yawflah tuoba detcartsid emaceb tub rewsna na detrats nalA dna
.nwo sih tsniaga desserp tsehc mils sih
.dessik yeht sa ruf tfos dna kciht eht gnippirg
.ton yllufepoh os
.redluohs eno fo ffo-flah
.mih fo tnorf ni amall sselhtaerb eht ta gnikool
.enohp sih tuo dellup dna flesmih ot deggurhs htieK
,kcab pets-flah a koot nalA
regit eht dniheb swor owT
.rab eht ot kcab emac yeht sa nirg a edih t’ndluoc hanoJ
,derettum dna delwocs nalA
…mu …ev’I ,em tsurT
htaerb gniydaets ,peed a koot nalA
.erovinrac gib a htiw moor dekcol a ni enolA
,elttil a revihs ydob s’htieK gnileef ,niaga delworg eH
.ezorf dna deknilb htieK
,flesmih ot terces sih tpek tsuj dah eh os
.ecaf tsenoh taht ni tnetni krad ro ecilam on was eh ,niaga ecnO
.seye sih gnisolc ,s’noil eht tsniaga kcab spil sih desserp dna
.tnorf eht raen edis eht ot ffo llah erutcel eht ni taes a koot dna
nameltneg redlo ylthgils siht taht detcepsus htieK dna
.stneduts eht ecaf ot yllanif denrut eh
,amall eht ta ylmraw delims nalA   2 fo 2 traP
.knis eht ot txen retnuoc eht no mih tis ot ylsseltroffe mih detfil dna
sregnif etaciled s’htieK elihw
.kcab dennirg nalA
.mih ta kcab dekool amall eht dna
.htaerb sih no tiurf dna rouqil fo llems eht dna ,htmraw s’amall eht leef dluoc eH
.elttil a ruf delffur sih tuo gnihtooms
,gnihtyna ro doom eht kaerb ot tnaw t’nod I …I-
,psag teiuq a evag noil eht dna ,selppin s’nalA fo eno ta yltfos desaet eugnot s’htieK .ruf
.suovren tlef htieK
,elttil a uoy ot no gnimoc neeb ev’I ,sey dna ,nam gnuoy evitcartta na er’uoY .htieK ,netsiL“
,tnemom a rof desuap eH
,elttil a tsuj pu elzzum sih detlit dna
”.noos niaga uoy ees ll’I epoh I
tekcaj tius sih fo tuo flesmih deggurhs nalA
.htieK ot kcab gninrut erofeb eldnah rood eht no kcol eht gninrut
”.anodlaG ta retsemes wen a ot emocleW
uoy ot detcartta m’I esuaceb tsuj tub
”,enohp ruoy em evig retteb d’uoy neht ,lleW“
”.tihs elttil uoy ,ereh netsiL“
.resolc pets flah rehtona koot eh sa hcuot s’noil eht otni keehc sih delzzun htieK  ”.oN
.dnah s’nalA fo kcab eht hsurb spitregnif sih gnittel ,drac eht koot htieK
xofnogarD nelarD yb
”.ti gnissim fo maerd t’ndluow I .taerg sdnuoS“
.deciton t’ndah I ?ti sI“
”.tseb eht er’uoY .hanoJ ,sknahT“
.flehs a fo renroc eht tsniaga yltnageleni depmub daeh s’htieK fo kcab ehT
.resolc mih gnixaoc yltneg dna
.tsehc sih nwod eit sih dehtooms dna
.tuo dnah sih gnidloh ,htieK dias
.taht fo erom detnaw rehtar eh taht
”.reganeet a ekil moorhtab eht ni syob etuc htiw tuo gnikam ,uoy ta kooL“ .delkcuhc hanoJ
,mih dnuora gnippils kcab sih no dnah eht
,esolc htieK gnigguh
”.ti ta elbirret tsuj m’I tub ,kcab trilf ot tnaw I ebyam ,lleW“
sredluohs sih revo gnidils sdnah daorb s’nalA tlef eH
.lliw I teb uoY“ .delims nalA
,rouqil hsrah eht ot desu ssel saw htieK
.mrod sih ot kcab yaw eht lla dennirg dna
.erofeb slrig dessik d’eH
?mih no noil llems llits elpoep dluoC
,nalA ta pu gnikool
.ssik eht ekorb nalA sa elttil a detnap htieK
,goD fo ecioV ehT rof rotarran a gnieb sevol ohw
”riA hserF fO htaerB A roF tuO gnippetS“   yojne esaelP
.gnitarebil saw ti dna ,efil sih ni erofeb siht ekil og
”.dnim ni taht peek ot erus eb ll’I .uoy knahT“
”.tops elttil taerg siht dnuof yltnecer I
,smra s’htieK rednu sdnah sih deppils noil eht nehw esirprus yb thguac saw neht
.ylteiuq deffuh nalA dna
”?stsaeb eht fo gnik sa egami ruoy ot od thgim erovibreh na gnitad tahw deirroW“
.pu gnilruc spil sih ,delims nalA  ”.yrros m’I“
deraelc eH  ?seye lufituaeb esoht ni was eh noitapicitna ti saW
.ruf eht hguorht selcsum s’noil eht gnileef
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
?yadirF no ot pu uoy era tahw ,oS“
W“ .kcab dellup dna detnap htieK  .tleb
,sih tsniaga tlem ydob s’amall eht tlef eH
.noitisop suoiracerp a rehtar otni teg ot flesmih dewolla dah eh taht dezilaer dna dewollaws eH
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.enod ti teg yletinifed ll’I won tub ,teef ym gniggard saw I dna ,elttil a eludehcs ym ecnalab ot erofeb ot dennalp dah I
.s’03 dim ro ylrae sih ni erehwemos-
,sruoh evlewt neeb neve t’ndah tI
,nalA ta pu dekool htieK
pu dehcaer dna yltfos dehgis htieK
,llah erutcel eht ssorca gnipeews ylfeirb reve ylno seye sih
.gnileer saw dnim s’htieK