.elttil a nwod gnimlac flesmih tlef htieK
.slootsrab eht fo eno otni dils dna
.won sraey wef a rof rehto hcae nwonk ev’eW
.mih dlot tsuj dah eh noitamrofni emas eht htiw ynnaD ot txet eht tnes dna enohp sih tuo dellup eH
”.uoy teem ot eciN .htieK“
.htieK tsniaga ylivaeh denael dna denrut drapoel knurd ylgnisaercni ehT
,gnidliub eht tsniaga denael dna
.yltnereffid uoy ees t’now yeht
.thgil siht ni dekool liatkcoc a yaw eht devol eH
”.gib eb ot gniog s’ti dna yademos ecalp nwo sih nwo ot gniog s’eH
.erovibreh elbarenluv emos
.knarF htiw yllaicepsE“
”?htieK ,flesruoy tuoba tib a em llet uoy t’nod yhw ,lleW“
,ynnaD ta kool ot denrut htieK
.rood eht dna mih neewteb saw noil eht tpecxE
.gnirahs ni detseretni ton er’uoy fi ssenisub ym fo enon si tahT“
.ylteiuq gnittahc dna dexaler erew snortap wef eht dna
noil eht dniheb pu emoc ot
ot gniyrt ereh uoy erA
”?mmh ,sevitom roiretlu oN“
,dedda ylkciuq dna taorht sih deraelc eH
.nalA rof gnitiaw
.thguoht ni tsol htieK dnif ot elbat eht ot kcab deklaw nalA
rab eht fo tuo deklaw dna seye sih dellor htieK
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.edom ytrap otni kcab ylsseltroffe gnidils ,ynnaD dias
.semitemos ynnaD htiw taht ekil m’I sseug I .riaf s’tahT“
”.elbatrofmocnu uoy gnikam rof ezigolopa ot tnaw tsuj I
.mih wollof ot htieK rof denokceb dna
.sessalc fo yad tsrif eht rof
.enecs ygoloxim eht ni remoc-dna-pu gnuoy a si hanoJ ,haeY“
,deilper dna elttil a delkcuhc noil ehT
.enecs s’htieK yllaer t’nsaw ecalp sihT
,nwod sknird eht tup eH
”.tops liatkcoc elbatrofmoc dna wen a rof gnikool syawla m’I
.seye sih dellor dna
.knird ot dah d’eh tnuoma eht htiw dezalg dna
”?gnihtemos ro elpuoc a uoy erA
”.tahc a evah llew sa thgim ew os
.rab eht ta em ta gnirats erew uoy tuB“
,em yonna yehT“ .deggurhs nalA
nalA ot gnihtemos yas ot gninruter erofeb
knird sih ot kcab denrut htieK
.snoitseuq fo lluf ylneddus saw eH
.dnuora dekool dna
,ezeerb looc eht tsniaga sdnah sih gnippuc
!em morf yawa yatS“
”?emit doog a ’nivah uoY !yddub ,yeH“
.denepo rood moorhsaw eht
.moor mrod sih ot kcab dluoc eh sa tsaf sa nur ot detnaw ylneddus eh dna
?laed ruoy s’tahW
.lufthgiled deedni saw knird ehT .pis a koot dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.liatkcoc eht hguorht thgil eldnac gnirekcilf eht gnihctaw
rab eht otni deppets htieK  ”.era ew ereH“
.knird sih fo pis rehtona koot dna taorht sih deraelc nalA
,enecs ruoy ton s’ti fi ,oS“
,niaga htieK ta dekool eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.ybraen ecalp liatkcoc elttil ecin a wonk I“
.tnurg deyonna na htiw decalper nirg sih ,detnurg nalA
”.htieK ,ecar a ton s’tI“
.lla ta ereh eb ot tnaw t’ndid tsuj eh ,dlot eb hturT
,rab eht ta uoy ta gnirats saw I yrros m’I
.t’ndid dad ym dnA
.sdneirf tsesolc ym er’yeht tub
…m’I dna ,ereht ni enecs ym t’nsaw ti taht yas tsuj s’teL“  ”.detiaw yllautca uoY
.drapoel bmud taht troppus ot tuo ylno saw eH
enoemos morf nrael nac htieK tahw dna
,deilper dna deknilb noil ehT
.etunim a ni tuo eb ll’I“
.dehgual htob yeht dna
dna gnol os rof pihsdneirf taht evah uoY
.noisiv larehpirep sih ni noil eht peek ot gniyrt ,pis rehtona koot dna
.tnemom a tsuj rof ynnaD nioj ot rab eht morf yawa deklaw dna pu doots htieK
.regna ot degnahc yletaidemmi noisserpxe s’ynnaD  ”.em ta gnikool speek ohw rab eht ta yug noil a s’ereht ,yeH“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,snoitnetni s’nalA tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
”?nam ,uoy rof mih hcnup og ot em deen uoY“
?tuoba lla saw rab eht ta gnirats eht tahw taht sI
.mih ta kool a fo tib a teg ot emit eht koot htieK
.huH“ .setunim fo elpuoc a retfa deraeppa noil ehT
.derruls ynnaD ”!htieK“
”.rab a ta erovinrac a yb ta derats gnitteg suovren
.rab eht dniheb gnihtemos ot seye sih detreva ydaerla dah eh tub
rab eht fo edis rehto eht dnuora og ot saw nalp siH
,yrotaderp eb ton thgim won thgir em gnivig er’uoy kool ehT“
elbat eht ot kcab gnilbbow
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”?ekil uoy od tahW
sdneirf laer er’yeht fi dna
”?knird a uoy yub I naC
rouqil nworb raelc eht dna ssalg skcor eht fo
.oot ,uoy ot ti txet ll’I
.redluohs s’htieK no dnah yvaeh a tup eh
.htieK ot ssalg sih desiar eH ”!sreehC
”.yaw eht yb ,nalA s’eman ehT
.taht tuoba derac stneduts wen eht fo enon tub
”.pu kooh ot ffo tnew yeht elihw
.demrala leef t’ndid eh taht desirprus leef did eH
.rab eht fo kcab eht ni semag gniknird deyalp ynnaD elihw rab eht ta knird teiuq ylevitaler a evah dluoc eH
.namgniw sih sa em detnaw dna liat gnisahc knarF gnikcuF .haeY“
,no dael ,esaelP .deugirtni
.knird sih no seye sih tpek htieK
?ti taht sI ?ruoved ot erovibreh emos rof tnuh
.niaga nalA ta pu dekool dna ,deddon htieK
?mih ot no gnimoc noil redlo siht saW
,xofnogarD nelarD yb
,resnepsid eht morf slewot repap emos debbarg dna sdnah tew sih ffo koohs htieK  ”.derob m’I dna
.dah d’eh sknird fo elpuoc eht retfa revarb elttil a gnileef saw htieK dna
.seye sih neewteb elzzum sih fo egdirb eht dehcnip htieK
.htieK ot etteragic a dereffo eH
.rab eht ot revo deklaw nalA sa dehctaw htieK  ”.kcab thgir eB
.esimorp I ,sevitom roiretlu oN
”.rehto hcae ot tnaveler ton era won era uoy erehw dna ega ruoy ta saw I erehW“
,pu sbmuht elbuod a htieK evag dna kcab denael ynnaD  ”!tilps
.yraw gnieb htrow s’ti
”?dias uoy ,uoy dehctid sdneirf ruoY
,xofnogarD nelarD yb ”riA hserF fo htaerB a rof tuO gnippetS“
.deggurhs dna taes sih otni dexaler htieK
rab eht ot pu deldis amall eht htieK   yojne esaelP   .3OA no
,htaerb peed a koot dna
.roirp setunim wef a tsuj mih ta gnirats neeb dah taht
”.ti htiw elbatrofmoc leef ot sraey em koot tI
.dias d’eh tahw dezilaer eh nehw gniklaw deppots eH
,derob htob er’ew ekil sdnuos tI“
.gnola emoc ot em deksa eh dna ,ereht ni no gniog soahc eht fo egrahc ni ylbisnetso saw enim fo dneirf A“ .deggurhs htieK
ot gniog m’I os ,worromot gniht tsrif sessalc tog ev’I
tnemevom s’noil eht sa deliocer dna ,depmuj htieK
!ereh lortnoc rednu sgniht tog ev’uoy ekil smeeS“
.tey tuo t’nsaw eh taht yltcerroc desseug dah nalA
.dluoc ylbissop eh sa gninetaerht-non sa kool ot gniyrt ,mih fo tnorf ni sdnah sih dedlof noil ehT
,yltfos dias dna sdnah sih desiar noil ehT
.amall eht deilper ”.sknaht ,oN“
,srae s’ynnaD fo eno otni kaeps ot pu denael htieK
.gniugirtni os dekool dah htieK tuB
.slaniru eht fo eno ot revo devom dna
.mih dniheb larroc ot gniyrt saw ynnaD taht mehyam eht erongi dna elttil a xaler ot gniyrt
.noitnetta sih teg ot redluohs eht yb drapoel eht debbarg eH
.tuo eno deppat dna setteragic fo kcap a tuo dellup noil ehT
.tuo eb ot gnitnaw ton rof enoemos erutcel ot tuoba ton m’I dna
,deddon dna delims nalA
,elbat eht no semit wef a ssalg sih denrut dna
,mih ot rab eht ssorca knird s’htieK dils rednetrab ehT
demees taht ekahsdnah a htiw nalA deteerg ohw noil rehtona saw rednetrab ehT
.saw nalA deugirtni erom eht
.gnos loohcs eht nrael ot gniyrt ylneknurd erew sraey-tsrif suocuar ylthgils eht erehw
.elihw gnol a rof toN
,knird sih fo pis rehtona koot eH
.rellams elttil a kool mih gnikam ,revo dehcnuh ylthgils saw eh tub
.egde no elttil a m’I sseug I .yrros m’I“
.niaga gnirats mih thguac htieK
.reverof meht nwonk ev’I dna ,puorg tink-thgit ytterp a er’eW
.ecneirepxe erom tib a htiw
,yltnereffid uoy ees ll’yeht ,rO
.gnihtaerb sih mlac ot gniyrt
.em no s’dnuor tsriF“
.uoy ot pu ti ekam em tel
.denoihsaF dlO taerg a ekam yehT“ .dennirg nalA
.rehctip eht yb gniyub no detsisni ynnaD taht reeb lufwa eht fo erom yna knird ot tnaw t’ndid eH
rof gnitnuh eb ot demees eh fi srecnuob eht fo eno ot klat neht
.ti yb demrala leef t’ndid htieK
.rab eht no sllib emos deppord htieK dna
.evael dna moorhtab eht esu ot gniog saw I .knird ym dehsinif I dna ,rab eht morf deraeppasid uoY ?uoy wolloF“
noitcifnaf )sratsaeB yltsom( sih dnif nac uoY
.hguoht ,retteb steg tI
.erovinrac regral ylsuoivbo na ot raef on gniwohs saw eH
”?ereht gniod uoy erew tahw
”.sselthguoht semitemos er’yeht esuaceb yawa sdneirf ruoy worht t’nod uoY
.reverof em ta yrgna eb ot naht efil sih ni nos sih evah rehtar d’eh taht dediced eh yllautneve tuB
.xim eht otni sdrow nwo sih fo emos worht ot detnaw dna
”.ti yb gnihtyna naem t’ndid I
.taht ot etaler nac I“
.luos a dlot t’ndah htieK
sa emoc ot mih deksa dah ynnaD
.era ew ereh os ,suoulfrepus saw ecneserp ym tuo snruT
”.emulov lluf ta cisum pop elbirret taht htiw ecalp siht ni noitasrevnoc a evah ot draH“ .dekrims htieK
,niaga mih ta gnikeep noil eht thguac eh ,netfo os yrevE
,oot em dehctid tub lla evah sdneirf yM
”.em morf gnihtemos tnaw thgim uoy ekil sleef ti tub
.mih ot gniklat saw eh yaw eht esnes edam ti desseug htieK
,esaelP .seigolopa yM“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.thgin bup a rof tuo stneduts wen eht fo lla ekat ot dereetnulov dah ohw dneirf siH
,dias dna rae s’ynnaD ot esolc ni denael htieK   .derruls drapoel eht
,mih tuoba denrael eh erom ehT
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
thguoht ni tsol saw htieK
rab eht fo dne eht ta noil redlo na was eh eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo dna
.meht no sraj ni seldnac laer htiw selbat wol dna setteuqnab dekcab hgiH
.dnah eerf sih htiw ffo noiton eht devaw nalA
”?ega ym ta tuo ydaerla uoy ereW“
.gninetaerht sseL
,gniyalp saw cisum zzaj woL
”?em ta gnirats erew uoy yhw taht sI
.eson sih fo egdirb eht ssorca erew sessalg erauqs llams fo riap a dna ,eit kcalb niht a htiw tius kcalb prahs a gniraew saw eH
,suoivilbo gnieb m’I fi em evigrof os ,elihw a rof gnihtyna ro gnitad yllaer neeb t’nevah I …oS“
.tius kcalB .sessalg erauqS
.niaga deddon noil ehT
.noil a ekil rotaderp a dnuora draug sih pord ot knird ot hguone dah ton yletinifed dah htieK
,terces ni erom elttil a mih hctaw dna
,mih ot yldneirf demees tsael ta nalA
renroc mid a ni elbat teiuq a ta mih nioj ot htieK detivni nalA
tnemom a rof derednop htieK
.dehgual nalA  ”?knarF dneirf dlo ruoy htiw nevE“
”?emit doog a gnivaH ?he ,ytrap avulleH“
”?denoihsaF dlO doog a ekam yeht oD
,em dehctid sdneirf yM
.eb nac ti redrah eht enoemos wonk uoy regnol ehT
ssalg tuc eht hguorht detcarfer emalf eldnac gnirekcilf eht dehctaw dna ,nattahnaM sih fo pis a koot nalA
.mih ta yldnik delims dna htieK ot txen hcneb hsulp eht otno deppils eH
,ria nmutua ylrae looc ylthgils eht otni
.dliub mils dna serutaef etaciled sih htiw amall eht ta gnikool
desucofnu ylthgils seye sih
.yeksihw elbuod a ekil dekool tahw fo mir eht revo mih ta gnireep saw taht
.nirg a htiw dias eh
.egnahc ot gnihtyna tnaw t’nod uoy
”.ffuts sih swonk yllaer dneirf rednetrab ruoy ,woW“
etarg rewes a otni ti dessot dna etteragic eht morf gard lanif a koot eH
.ytrap a detnaw yehT
.yawyna gniod saw I tahw naht nuf erom ekil sdnuos tI .eniF“
,rab rehto eht ta amall eht fo ffo seye sih ekat ot elba neeb t’ndah eH
”.lamina emas eht sa uoy ees llits ll’yeht tub
,gnicar saw traeh siH
”.mih rof sruovaf gniod syawla tsuj em fo daetsni tniop taht ot teg ll’ew tniop emos ta erus m’I
,ti thgil ot hguone gnol klaw sih ni desuap eH
”.thgiarts s’eh ,sediseB .oN“
,knird sih fo pis a koot eH
.niaga redluohs eht no ynnaD deppat htieK
worromot revognah a fo hcum oot htiw pu dne t’ndluow eh depoh eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”?moorhtab eht otni em wollof uoy did yhW
.ssem a eb ot gniog saw tI
.gard gnol a koot dna
”?uoy ot ti gniod peek yeht fi meht ruomuh yhW
elttil a eb thgim I yhw dnatsrednu uoy erus m’I dna
.neddih swalc sih ,mih fo tnorf ni yletilop dedlof sdnah sih tpek eH
,erovibreh na ni tseretni na fo hcum taht sekat erovinrac egral a emit ynA
.deddon dna dehgis nalA  ”.evorppa t’now dad ym deirrow m’I“ ,ylteiuq dias eH
”riA hserF fo htaerB a rof tuO gnippetS“
.sruovaf mih gniod peek uoy fi mih rof ssendnof fo dnik emos evah tsum uoy ,lleW“ .delkcuhc nalA
,tnasaelp saw redluohs sih no dnah s’noil eht fo htmraw ehT
,sdnah sih gnihsaw saw eh elihw dna ,flesmih deveiler eH
.ecnad railimaf a ekil sdnuos ti ebircsed uoy yaw ehT“ .dekrims htieK
,s’noil eht tsniaga mir eht deknilc dna ssalg sih pu dekcip eH
,secnatsmucric dna snosaer nwo rieht sah enoyrevE
,goD fo ecioV ehT rof rotarran a gnieb sevol ohw
”.seillof ym htiw gnola gniyalp sthgin fo ytnelp tneps s’eh ,sediseB“
”.tnorf tuo uoy teem ll’I
.swalc sih fo lla ffo dewohs
.erusnu llits ,noil eht ta derats htieK
.eci dehsurc fo sknuhc yb pu nekorb
.nalA ta kcab delims dna ,semit fo elpuoc a deknilb htieK
.gnorts oot gnihtoN“
”.sessalg erauqs ,tius kcalb ,rab eht ta noil
.noitasrevnoc a dloh dluoc eh erehw cisum yzzaj wol htiw egnuol liatkcoc teiuq a ni emoh ta erom hcum saw eH
,elbuort yna tnaw t’nod I .esaelp ,oN“
,enif s’tahT ?tey ,tuo toN“
.rab til-kcab elpma eht fo weiv doog a htiw
.esle gnihtemos saw yllaer amall sihT
,erovinrac egral a ylsuoivbo saw noil ehT
,knird sih fo pis rehtona koot htieK
,ylsselerac derewsna dna
,ega gniknird fo erew ohw stneduts wen eht rof sessalg gnillifer
.ti tuoba eltbus eb ot gniyrt
,lortnoc fo tuo yldliw teg t’ndid sgniht erus ekam dna dnuora kcits ot dedeen eh ekil tlef llits htieK
enola rab eht ta em tfel ydnA dna eh os ,oot suoulfrepus saw I tuo snruT
.denoihsaF dlO eno ,era uoy erehT“
erovinrac a htiw ecaps desolcne na ni gnieb cinap fo tnemom a tlef htieK
.roiretni til-wol eht otni htieK gnitivni ,rab liatkcoc llams a ot rood eht denepo eh erofeb
”.thgiarts htob er’ew …mu
”.yako s’ti …tsuj ,yeH“
.yletilop delims noil ehT
.moorhsaw eht esu ot dedeen eh tsrif tuB
.seye rebma gib s’amall eht ni ecnad emalf s’eldnac eht dehctaw dna
”.delaes era spil ym
.eniw der a deredro dna noitnetta s’rednetrab eht tog eH
noitcerid s’htieK ni revo dekool eh dna mih ot gnihtemos dias nalA
.setunim evif ni noitasrevnoc siht gnivah rebmemer neve d’eh tcepsus t’ndid htieK
.dehgual dna ekoms fo duolc a tuo welb nalA
.tnemom eht ta ytpme ylluficrem saw hcihw moorhtab eht ot dworc eht hguorht yaw sih dehsup htieK
.ekilssenisub naht yldneirf erom
deggurhs noil ehT
”!nepo seye ym peek ll’I !htieK ,yakO“
,ytisrevinu eht ta raey tsal rieht otni gniog yllufsseccus enoemos fo elpmaxe emos
.elttil a deggurhs htieK
,dias dna taes hcneb eht otni deppils htieK
.wonk uoy tel ot detnaw tsuj I .ynnaD ,oN“
”?ti teg ot diputs oot tsuj m’I dna ,thgin lla em ta gnitrilf neeb uoy evah tub
”?thgir ,tey tuo ton m’I yhw si em ksa ot tnaw yllaer uoy tahW“
,thgiarts er’eW“
,semitemos doog si egnahc tuB
.oot yag saw eh ebyam ekil leef htieK edam ereh yaw eht no noitasrevnoc eht dna
.serovibreh etad yllamron t’ndid eh hguoht neve
,em fo kcart esol uoy fi tub ,nalp a tog ev’I
.soahc eht otni evid ot deen t’ndid eh tub
,noil eht ta revo dekool dna
,htieK ot denrut ynnaD
”.tsael ta ,em rof did tI