dna artnam noitatidem ym denialpxe I elihw ybriK ta kool ot detfihs d'I
.derab sgnaf sih htiw ecaf ym ta gnipael ,delwoh eh "!egrahC"
",setunim ytriht ni krow ffo teg I"
.tegguN no dexif ezag ym tpek I hguohtla
em no decnavda sgod ruoF
.dnah a tuo kcuts dna delims eH ".dnah
.tfel I sa em ot eybdoog dekrab eH .mih deifillom
.liam gnireviled fo sraey ym gnirud htiw laed ot dah d'I snamuh eht fo tsom naht etilop erom neeb dah god ehT
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
,doohrobhgien lairtsudni eht ni tuo gnittis gnidliub etercnoc ,yarg gib
.elcric-imes deggar a ni
,goj a rof enog tsuj d'eh fi sa drah gnihtaerb dna gnitaews saw eH
,sseccus tuohtiw god ym niart ot gnihtyreve deirt ev'I
.em ta gninraw a delworg dna snac-hsart owt neewteb morf tuo daeh sih dekop yarts a dna
,tegguN sdrawot noitnetta rieht denrut sgod ruof llA ".ti
.egac eht fo kcab eht tsniaga llab thgit a ni pu delruc saw auhauhihC nat llams A
,pleh ot ereh revo nar I yhw s'tI
.deluam teg ot gniog erew uoy thguoht I"
"?tegguN nekcihC" .seye suoblub
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
",tegguN ,uoy knahT"
yldipar taeb ot nugeb dah traeh yM
ereh tog I emit eht yb tub
.ylimaf yppah gib
.tegguN ,ezigolopa I"
.tuo meht enut ot tseb ym did I
.liat sih deggaw dna
esruc reh htiw laed ot woh tuo erugif ot gniyrt saw anauJ ,emit tsaL
.nwod flesym mlac ot gniyrt ,detnahc I
"!em detailimuh ehs tuB"
.ton ro ygrene desufed
.gniggoj neeb d'yeht fi sa htaerb rof gniffuh tub ,esolc saw rekaeps ehT .dias enoemos
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
,flesym yojne ot detrats yllautca d'I emit hcnul yB
".regnif a tfil ot evah t'now uoY
lortnoc fo tuo htob
,rehtegot sdnah ym detsiwt I
.gnihtyna naem t’ndid taht tub
mih htiw sdnah koohs I ".anauJ m'I
.uoy ot gniklat ton era sgod eht ,yenoh ,anauJ"
.smelborp ym rof uoy emalb ot deirt evah t'ndluohs I"
,ekahs ot eno derujni ym mih nevig ylsuoicsnocnu d’I ezilaer I did nwod dna pu mra reh depmup eh sa ylno dna
.tegguN ta neht dna
,kcap eht no kcab ym nrut ot aedi dab a eb dluow ti edisni erehwemos wenk I
.tuo mih nworht d'yeht dna
t'nsaw I  2 fo 2 traP
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.esolc os gnidnats mih dessim d’I taht
.torrac tsal eht gnihcnurc dehsinif eh retfa deksa yarts eht "?worromot eroM"
god a rof gnikool no desucof os neeb d’I taht dessarrabme ,mih decaf dna
.etunim a naht ssel ni dnah ruoy fo tuo staert gnitae ot gniggaw liat ot noissergga morf sgod esoht koot uoY"
.weiv morf dehsinav daeh s’god ehT
.em gnivigrof saw eH
.eye eno revo tops eht htiw yarts yhs eht dna llab-
.lla ta truh t’ndid tsirw ym tey
.tegguN ot gniklat tpek dna mih derongi I
.pu gnikool ,depmuj I dna kcurt ym fo dooh eht raen taorht rieht deraelc nosrep A
.em dniheb gnulf smra ym htiw klawedis eht no ssa ym no drah dednal I
",siht no dlos ton llits m'I"
.dnuora lrihw em edam em dniheb morf lworg a tub ,doots I
.xim yksuH yffulf
,rae eno gnitfil ,em ta daeh sih dekcoc eH
.elims a desserppus I ".anauJ
”auhauhihC ylnedduS“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,dniw eht yb deteffub
,god.ecioveht ta
.staes eht neewteb dehcuorc tegguN nekcihC laever ot yawa ti gnignilf
,gib a revo gniooc
,ydaerla edisni yawflaH
",tegguN ,thgirla s'tI"
?uoy gnisruc fo em esucca uoy neht dnA" .deffins tegguN
.reh desruc skniht ehs taht
"?ot gniklat uoy era ohw ,anauJ"
.tegguN retfa ffo dettort dna ,deifsitas
.eson reh delknirw
.elims dna pots em edam tahT
.meht gniwollof erofeb ylregnig em deffins dna
.kcap eht fo tuo gnikael saw ygrene ehT
sgod llams ,slrig rebmemeR"
,nwod dekool dna denrut I
.tnemeerga rieht dekrab sgod owt rehto eht
,pu deraer auhauhihC-renni yM
.gnilims saw I edisni tub
.deppots dna nwod slennek wef a devom yehT
ylimaf sih tcetorp saw od ot detnaw dah god elttil eht llA
.degnul eh erofeb edisni nettog d'eh woh rednow ot emit dah ylerab I
dees noilednad a ekil
.doolb gniyrd fo senil niht owt erew sdnuow eht fo ot deniamer taht lla ;enog ydaerla erew tfel dah eh sehctarcs ehT
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,yad gnikrow eritne eht rof namuh
.gab hcnul ym tlef I litnu nwod dnah ym gninnur neht dna
auhauhihc eht ,tegguN nekcihC
".yrt erom eno ti evig ot gnilliw m'I
.sgod ruoy ffo llac ,tegguN"
kcap eht ot ssenkaew wohs ot ton em gnillet
",snamuh ruoy ot sgniht gnireviled tsuj m'I"
ayaT ".em ta gnikool s'ti ,.G.M.O"
sesicrexe gnihtaerb did dna klawedis eht no deggel-ssorc nwod delttes I os
.sgod yna ees t'ndid tub
.yrotirret ruoy ot ssecca feirb em gniwolla rof
yalpsid taht gnihctaw retfa tub
.gnihsulb ,dettimda I
",gnihtemos saw taht ,woW"
,emoclew era uoY" .daetsni dias I
.nwod kcab gniyal erofeb lennek eht fo tnorf eht ot saw kcab sih os ,detfihs dna pu tog eH
ybbol eht hguorht dessap eW ".gnihtemos
.tegguN rof tpecxe
.deneppah gnihton tub
.dnah ni llew sgniht dah uoy
.seY" "?gniniart goD"
.eye ym fo renroc eht ni deraeppa tegguN
.hteet gnippans s’tegguN morf ecaf ym tcetorp ot smra ym pu gnignilf
.uoy knaht ,llew ,hO"
"?ko ,stneilc ruoy rof tca ruoy evaS
noitciF degnaF yb dehsilbup seires seidoB gnignahC eht etorw ohw
drawrof dekcirp srae sih htiw pu emac yarts ehT
.raeh ot emit ni gniyas saw eh tahw ot kcab dna mra delaeh ylsuolucarim ym morf yawa noitnetta ym erot I dna niaga gniklat saw boR
.laed gib on saw ti tuB
.sregnif ym no eson dloc a fo hcuot eht tlef I esirprus ym oT
.niks ym ni ssenthgit gnilgnit eht leef dluoc I dna
.ecalp otni llef tser eht dna sgod htiw yaw siht dah I derevocsid tsuj I
,sliat rieht deggaw sgod owt rehto eht dna ifiF .mih derussa I
,gnippots ,dias I ",ereht iH"
.esirprus ni gnimaercs ,rood eht fo tuo sdrawkcab llef I sa dellimdniw smra yM
,gnikahs erew yeht gnizilaer
,savnac eht barg ot revo denael dna detsiwt I
.mih ta ylteews delims I .delbmurg ybriK
,eye sih dnuora tops etihw evitcnitsid eht dezingocer I
.dnah ym dehcuot yltneg dna
,esuoh siht ta god a rof dessap taht foop
,rood eht morf nwod slennek owt doots slrig ehT
,tegguN ta dekool dna deppots sgod owt ehT
.aera gniweiv god eht sdrawot ybbol eht hguorht gnitlep ydaerla erew yeht tub ,dellac I
retsis reh debbarg ehS ".og
.krow rof dedaeh dna
.evaw feirb a em evag dna mra sih desiar eH
,yltnatropmi tsom ,dna ,lortnoc-ni
.etaciled dna sselecarg ecno ta saw taht poh a htiw tuo depmuj eH
telracs dehsulb I ".desserpmi
.uoy ta tuo dehsal I taht yrros m'I"
nwod kcart sa llew sa
tih I sa kcarc gnippop a evag tsirw thgir yM
,relevart wollef ruoy
”auhauhihC ylnedduS“   yojne esaelP
.tsrif sih dehsinif yarts ehT ".yrotirret
"?gniht suoedih taht
,klaw eht nwod dekcab I
.god eht ta yltcerid gnikool ton tub
,em ta yllufepoh dekool eH ".reh
",worromot uoy fo hcae rof skcans retteb gnirb ll'I"
nosinu ni dednopser htob tegguN dna ybriK "?tahW" ".eno
eracs ot tnaw t'nod eW !ylno
"?gniniart god ecnaleerf
.srallod derdnuh owt uoy yap ll'I"
,yppahnu ylraelc ,delrans tegguN
,esuoh eht morf emac sdnuos oN
.gnihtemos ro enaD taerG a tuo kcip slrig eht erofeb ,pu yrruh ,woN
,dnah ym tsniaga detser llits taht elzzum sih fo dne eht tep ot hguorht regnif a hcaer ot detpmet saw I .dias I
,yltneloiv gnilbmert saw ohw
.lennek eht fo tnorf
.moC tod rettiwT fo yletal
.edisni srettel eht gnippils
mra ym dezarg hteeT
.tsirw deniarps a htiw etuor ym hsinif ot gniog saw I woh gnitalpmetnoc
dias eh ",llitS" .dias I
"?yawyna morf emoc cihcysp god a emoceb ot noitaripsni neddus siht did erehW"
redisnoc uoy dluoW"
",ylimaf ym fo ssol eht tuoba em tnuat t'nod ,namuh ,yawa oG"
eno eb ot gniog er'eW"
.ylwols gaw ot gnitrats liat
,torrac netaenu sih ta eson sih pu denrut
"?redavni ,seirotirret ruo lla ot gnimoc peek yhw nehT"
.yad s'god elttil eht edam tsuj d'I taht gnileef eht dna
rood eht dekcolnu I
.sevlesmeht yap t'ndluow sllib eht revewoh
,keew dab a dah ev'I
",nwod wols ,ayaT ,airaM"
,boR iH" ".boR s'eman yM"
.noisserpxe nopu-tup a htiw em gnihctaw neeb d'ohw ,ybriK no nups I
.ti rof uoy emalb ot deirt evah t'ndluohs I tub
.emoh tog I nehw sevlowerew eht tuoba etisbew ditpyrC eht daerer ot devloser I
tnemyap meht redisnoC"
,pleh ot desimorp ydaerla evah slrig ehT"
,yllis tib a tlef I
,eson retnec-ffo na gnilaever
,kcab dehcnilf dna depley I
.tegguN em ot ecin saw ehS"
.ecnahc a dnats t'ndluow I
.emoh lla meht ekat ot detnaw I dna
.kcurt eht fo edis eht tih I litnu yawa kcab
.llew sa raelc saw noitcerid rehtie ni klawedis ehT
yella na yb dessap I
,tpurretni ot naem t'ndiD"
.sgod elbatpoda htiw aera eht deretne dna
.seye god-yppup lufluos ,gib htiw
.eciov sih morf enog erif eht
eson rieht gnilknirw htob dna
staert eht no gniwang nageb lla yehT
# .tnuoma eht ta elggob ot ton gniyrt ,dias I
tub pleh t'ndluoc I tub
"tespu teg I nehw god a otni nrut I won dna em tib taht auhauhihC ylgu ,ynit a evah yeht esuaceb liam rieht reviled t’ndid I ,ma’am ,yrros"
htiw daeh egral yllacimoc a dna ,etib-rednu na
.god yffulf ,gib eht morf yawa meht deoohs I ".tisiv
em no saw kcap eht elihw degnahc I fI
".arac aneub ,opmeit lam A .arac aneub ,opmeit lam A" .detnahc dna ,seye ym desolc
.htob meht ot gniylper ,dias I
.kcurt eht fo tnorf eht ta doots nam A ".em esucxE"
.reh kcatta t'ndluohs eW
.htaerb a tuo welb boR ".seY"
,sdnomaid latem eht hguorht sregnif ym depparw dna tuo dehcaer I
.anauJ ,uoy evigrof I"
,leef yb xobliam eht denepo I sa rood god eht tfel reven seye yM
,dnah ym ni srettel fo elip eht ta nwod delwocs I
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.reh deye ybriK ",tub
dezis-llabteksab ,etihw ,yffulf eht ot gniklat
.elims a gnisserppus ,dias I
.taes edis s’revird eht no dnal ot ffo decnuob eh dna
.ti retfa pu gnibmilc erofeb edisni gab ytpme eht gnuws dna
.bmot a sa llits saw esuoh ehT
.detlah llab-ffulf etihw ehT
,emoceb ev'uoy remlac hcum woh ro ni gnignirb er'uoy yenom artxe eht lla tuoba nialpmoc t'nac I .taht tuobA"
.swaj sih ni ecnuob yppah a htiw ti thguac yarts ehT
.dias tegguN ",namuh-god
.su fo daeha srood ssalg eht hguorht yldeticxe dehsup ohw ,slrig eht dniheb deliart I dna dnabsuh yM
a saw gnidliub yteicoS enamuH ehT
,arac aneub ,opmeit lam A .decnavda sgod evif lla gninraw rehtruf yna tuohtiW ".nossel
.elbuort fo tuo god eht peek ot yad eht gnirud dnuora eb ll'I dna
,kcurt eht ta derats dna denrut I
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
drawrof srae sih dekcirp tegguN ".uoy
.gnilworg dna daeh sih ot kcab dennip srae
,niaga em ta dekrab bal kcalb ehT
.etuor ym htiw no eunitnoc ot hguone delttes tlef I litnu
"'.edanomel otni snomel nrut'
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
knil niahc eht otni llef dna depmuj I .dias ybriK
.hcnurc elgnis a htiw torrac s'tegguN pu deppans dna drawrof degnul yarts ehT
enog erew yeht erus saw I ecnO
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
",worromot erom ,seY"
,mlac niamer ot ytiliba ym ni tnedifnoc tey
.enod saw I sa noos sa evael dluow dna srenwo reh ot liam gnireviled saw I taht denialpxe dna
.uoy desuac I elbuort yna rof ygolopa erecnis ym tpecca esaelp ,tegguN nekcihC"
.moC tod rettiwT fo yletal
,ti revo llef wodahs ym sa pu dekool tI
.em ediseb ybriK nettogrof d'I taht tegguN no desucof os neeb d'I
.sllib fo daw a em dewohs dna tellaw sih tuo dellup eH ".srallod
niaga yarts eht fo thgis thguac I
.ylmrif dna ylwols ,dias I
;meht fo owt dezingocer I
trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT       ".ylimaf
.esuoh s'tegguN ot tog I neht tub
tpoda ot gniog s'ohw ,woW"
.daeh sih koohs dna
yradnuob yrotirret sih tcepser dluow I taht ecnarussaer kciuq a tub
.tisiv ot semoc ehs nehw alleB
em ediseb nwod tlenk ybriK ".hsinapS
kcab em detloj tih ehT
,debborht tsirw derujni yM
.eerf ti tog sgut kciuq wef A
elims a htiw xobliam eht tfel I tub
.desserpmi etiuq saw I
.meht fo hcae ot eno gnissot ,sgod fo gnir eht dnuora tnew I nehT
".ylimaf ym tcetorp ot detnaw reve ylno I"
.yawa skcolb wef a
.daeh sih dekcoc yarts ehT ".em
.tegguN ta detniop I
.seirotcaf dna sesuoheraw neewteb dehsauqs
.stneilc tisiv I nehw em htiw ti ekat neve nac I
,flesym decudortni ,deppots I
.hgis a htiw xaler I did em dniheb ylmrif dehctal saw etag eht retfa ylnO
.su neewteb ecaep eligarf eht tpursid ot tnaw t'ndid I tub
,etuor ym no god txen eht gnirongi naht rehtaR
.roolf eht tih gab eht erehw morf emac lworg ykaeuqs a ",hcuO"
.nossel a uoy evig ot si sihT
.tniop a sah ifiF"
meht dessot tsuj I fi neppah dluow tahw no flesym htiw gnitabed
"--ton m'I ,yrros m'I"
niap eht derongi I tub
?anauJ ,gnorw gnihtemos sI"
.reilrae em ot ylecin deklat namuh sihT
.uoy dlot I" .deggurhs I
.daol rehtona rof kcurt liam ym ot kcab dedaeh I os
,gnorw og sgniht nehw'
"?ereh gniod uoy era tahW"
.egac eht ni kcab rehtruf god eht ta gnitniop ,delggig airaM
.seye ym ta dekcirp sraeT
.hsinapS kaeps t'nod I wonk uoY
foop etihw ,ynit eht
.esirprus ni mih ta deknilb I
",uoy tsniaga gnihton evah I
.emarf rood eht fo egde eht no deppils teef ym dna
,etuor ym morf sgod esoht fo tsom wonk I
.rood kcurt eht sdrawot eldis ot ytinutroppo eht koot I os
.em htiw tcaretni neve t'nod snamuh eht fo tsoM
.og s'tel ,nom'C"
.kcab ym pu yaw eht lla niap fo skraps gnidnes ti fo kcohs eht ,depsag I dna
.rehtruf xaler em depleh hcuot siH
,ylthgil dednal eh tey
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rosivrepus ym htiw ylf dluow
.psag a htiw dias I
ria eht hguorht delialf sgel ruof siH
.kcans a sa tpek syawla I storrac ybab eht tuo dellup dna gab eht deppiznu sa
,skooB goD wobniaR dehsilbup
",em draeh uoY" .etsatsid ni
.sgod a fo noitatimi tseb ym ni hteet ym gniwohs dna gnilworg ,dias I
”auhauhihC ylnedduS“ fo
neht dna ifiF ".enod ti redisnoC"
.yawa gniknils erofeb skcolb lareves rof em dewodahs eH
,em ta yldetraeh-flah delworg eh
si ti yllaretiL .moidi na s'tI"
taes s'revird eht fo egde eht tuo gnileef ,kcab dehcaer I
.rehtaef a sa thgil dna
.sgod fo kcap taht deldnah uoy woh was I tub
kniht t’ndid I ,revewoH
,suoires noisserpxe ym tpek I .dekrab eh
ot esolc si ti sseug I hsilgnE nI '.gnilims peek
.trihs pu-nottub a dna skcals gniraew saw eh hguohtla
.kcatta esirprus sih gnirud em deppin dah tegguN erehw ,mra ym ta nwod decnalg I
.no deunitnoc dna deggurhs I
revo emoc dah tegguN taht was I
".uoy tnuat ot ereh ton m'I"
,ytpme saw gab yM
,seye sih dellor tsuj d'eh wenk I dna detrons ybriK ".smelborp
.gnirevoc citsalp kcils eht ffo thgir dils sdnah ym tub taes eht barg ot deirt I
kcab decnalg I nehw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.em ta pu derats tegguN ".uoy
.ffo gnicar tnew dna
.em ot klat ot tnaw t’ndid god a fi gnihtyna od t’ndluoc I
.detcejer ylkciuq os d'yeht god eht ees ot suoiruc ,revo detfird I
.etuor ym htiw no tnew dna etag eht revo
.eno siht gnitpoda er'eW"
.ten.relleknosidam no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.ria eht ni torrac taf a gnissot ,dias I ",og uoy ereH"
keeW krahS detide dna
-- arac aneub ,opmeit lam a --decitcarp d'I taht esicrexe noitatidem artnam ym detaeper I
",god eht ot gniklat saw I"
",meht htiw troppar a dah ydaerla I os
.god emas eht saw ti wenk I os
em ta pu gnikool saw dna
.elsia eht nwod ffo devom yeht dna
.noitareneger fo srewop gnizama dah syawla sevlowerew eht seivom eht nI
sgnirts traeh ym ta deggut pleh rof seirc evitnialp 'sgod ehT