.kcen sih fo kcab eht no niks fo ffurcs eht ssapmocne ot pirg ym detfihs I os
.nwod gnimlac retfa kcab degnahc ylno dna yrgna neeb d’I
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.laets ot enoyna rof ,hsub a rednu ereh gnittis tsuj sehtolc dna gab ym evael erad t’ndid I ,sulP
,ereh fo tuo teg ot dedeen I dna
.yrotirret ym fo tuo teG
.seohs no gnittup yldrawkwa
elpuoc gnirats eht dniheb pu dellup rac dnoces A
rof gnihcraes deirt I
.egapemoh elgooG eht gniwohs rerolpxE tenretnI htiw ,no llits saw retupmoc ehT .ksed eht otno neht dna
kcen ym gninarc dna
,rood eht ni palf eht nees d’I
.enohp llec ym dna
# .yaw a ni ,eurt saw hcihW
.yawa gniklaw deeps erofeb xob eht otni srettel eht gnippop
retal stnemom wef A .em dnuora mra sih gniworht ,pu
,ydob eritne ym revo llef cirbaf yvan tfos retal tnemom A
.detatiseh neht tub ,txet eht tnes I
?neht I saw tahw ,tuB .noom lluf a no gninrut t’nsaw I
,htnom siht rof tegdub eht ni ton saw stnap fo riap wen A
",ydaer tsomla s'renniD"
.god egnarts eht no gnitaluceps dna
.noops gnivres eht deppord sregnif
gnilbmert ym dna
.elbat eht morf em ta kcab derats gniraperp ruoh tsal eht tneps d’I doof fo sdnuom ehT ".esuoh
,swap dehctertstuo ym no gnitser daeh ,ereht yal I
.satijaf rof spirts kaets eht gniyrf dna seiggev eht gnicils nageb I sa ylsuoiruf
.namow eht sdrawot tuo mih dleh dna tegguN detfil I
dnim ni taht htiW
,ecneserp ym gnissimsid ylraelc
.edecer ot nageb ruf ym dna delgnit niks ym tub ,ti dereggirt tahw erus t’nsaw I
.retupmoc eht no denrut I yad eht rof tfel dah sdik eht dna ybriK retfA
tuo tog I emit eht yB
,yltnesba derewsna I
".redavni ,ylreporp uoy llik nac I os nwod em tuP"
,sgel reh ta dnuora depmuj I
yltneloiv os gnilbmert
".dloc gnitteg renniD"
.noitamrofni lufesu yna dleiy t'ndid hguorht gnillorcs tub
.esuoh s'icatS ta eta ydaerlA .won emoh yaw nO"
seuqinhcet gnimlac
gnihtolc ym fo eerf dehsarht I nehW
,serutaerc pmaws ,seimmum ,stsohg ,seibmoZ
,deb ot tnew yeht yllaniF
"?neeb uoy ev’erehW ?anauJ"
detartsurf ni nwod esuom eht demmals I  .gnihtoN
,reh dniheb rood eht tuhs dna esirprus ni
tsuj uoy diD ?tahW"
.gib oot tsuj saw
",lerriuqs daed ruoy tnaw t’nod I"
ev’I gniht tseilgu eht saw eH
.noitarepsaxe laer fo remmilg saw ti htaenrednu tub
,palf eht dekcol d'I erus rof thguoht I
,traeh gnidnuop ym ydaets ot htaerb peed a koot I
htrof dna kcab deggaw liat ehT
#  .yllaer htnom yna ro
.sdrow eht htiw gnola enohp eht hguorht eralg ym dnes dluoc I fi sa
.nehctik ynit eht ni neve
wap auhauhihC ynit ym neve tub ,nrettap
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.thgit eciov ym gnikam regna
.yawyna tuo teg ot seganam syawla lived elttil siht wohemos tub
.esruc neddus reh htiw slaed anauJ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,trapa rehtraf gnimoceb sllaw eht
,riahc ym ni kcab denael I
yllaer god taht daH
.tnemredliweb ni dnuora dereep ehS
,seitnewt ylrae reh ni ylbaborp ,namow A
,kcen eht fo kcab eht yb gniht ynit eht debbarg dna revo denael I  .ydob yldnips
,moordeb eht otni yaw ym deot-pit I sa teef erab ym no dloc saw roolf doowdrah ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,yawa dereggats I
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
,derif eb dluow I dna
.ecneserp sti deretsiger ylerab
,depyt I "?u r erehW"
.retal setunim wef a deilper ,tsegnuoy ym ,ayaT ".uoy evoL
.god elttil eht ta deralg dna daeh reh koohs ehS ".yawyna
,tiucric ym gnitelpmoc retfa kcurt liam ym ni kcaB
,ecnesba ym no gnitnemmoc hcae
.hteet dehctamsim s'auhauhihC eht morf gnuh stnap ym morf cirbaf eulb fo parcs A
.deb otni deppils dna
.thginrevo moorhtab eht ni dekcol elihw esucxe na pu kniht ot emit fo tol a dah d’I ".tuo
,stekcop ym rebmemer em edam sehtolc ym tuoba gniknihT
deffuh bal kcalb ehT ".yaw
.htuom sti denepo bal kcalb ehT
.mih dniheb desolc gnimmals rood tnorf eht
.taht tuoba yrros os m'I"
esrow werg gnikahs ehT
.worromot tset a rof gniydutS"
.enola moorhtab a otni em gnittuhs
namow delevehsid a saw nees d’yeht lla os ,no trihs dna stnap ym nettog d’I emit taht yB
.egde eht revo tuo dekaep renroc a litnu
tuo yaw ym gud I .cirbaf fo
.em diova ot teerts eht gnissorc ,delley eh
.niaga gnikahs nageb ydob elohw yM "?tahW"
ydob elohw yM .eulb elap
.ytluciffid htiw sehtolc fo dnuom eht fo tuo delggurts I
.skcals ym ot egamad eht enimaxe ot gel ym pu dellup I
degnahc d’I emit hcaE
?niaga deneppah siht fi tahW
no stsop detnirp I
,hgual deltrats a evig em edam segapbew
,erutuf eht ni reh gnittis god eb ll'eW"
.egap dnoces eht ot revo dekcilc I os
,saw tluser tsrif ehT
.dekwag dna deppots klawedis eht no em sdrawot gniklaw nam A
.seivom eht nees d’I .flowerew a
.skrab ylno draeh yeht ,ayaT ekil tub
.dednal eh erofeb mih thguac esuoh eht morf namow eht tub
.moor gnivil eht otni tuo dettort I
.erever rieht fo tuo revird eht detloj hcihw
?no gniog saw tahW
,erawreppuT eht tog dna delworg I
,relevart wollef ruoy
enohp eht gnivom noitarbiv eht
.dedlocs eciov eninimef a ",god dab uoY
.flesreh ot derettum ayaT
niks ym revo nar ssenthgit gnilgnit A
.rednu gnidih neeb d’I hsub nekorb eht fo sniamer eht yb delaecnoc yllaitrap ylno
,dellif ydaerla d’I reniatnoc a otni llef tI
.ten.relleknosidam no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
gninrom siht nalp dnarg a dah d’I
.sreniatnoc citsalp eht otni doof eht gnipoocs nageb I sa regna htiw koohs sdnah yM
saw enoemos fi sa tlef liam fo gab yM
prahs a htiw yaw evag stnap ym dna redrah deggut I
,yltcaxe ,ytriht-evif tA
.lortnoc-fo-tuo ro ,ytsrihtdoolb
,weiv otni emac ruf nworb tfoS
,neercs eht no erutcip s’rethguad ym ta eralg ot gniworran seye
,god a eb ot saw I fI
!tegguN nekcihC !tegguN"
.dnuora enoyna nees t’ndah I sa
!tuoba gniklat era uoy tahw wonk t’nod I ?esruC"
,dessih I ",esruc eht kaerb ot woh em lleT"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.esu on saw ti tub
.esuoh eht otni kcab gniraeppasid erofeb
evots eht tfel I fI .delley I
.rewsna na ot resolc on em thguorb hcraeser fo sruoh owt rehtonA
.enohp eht no dekrow I elihw dedisbus dah gnilbmert yM
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.ksed eht no sregnif ym gnimmurd
",lerriuqs daed ym si sihT
.delworg eciov wol A
.eerf ti deggut dna hteet ym ni enohp eht fo egde eht koot I
.ayaT ot detxet I ".yadretsey tuobA"
.gnip rehtona neht
,sdrow esruc fo ynatil a htiw gnihtolc ym fo pot no tas neht dna
.ti tuoba mih ksa dluoc I os ,emoh saw eh depoh I
,elkna ym rof degnul eh sa tsuj ralloc sih yb tegguN gnihctac ,dehcuorc dna denrut I
",cigam" ",sehctiw" ",sesruc"
,ffits gninrom txen eht pu ekow I
.detfihsepahs flowerew ehT
.ylper t'ndid dna
.denruter I nehw em htiw eton s’rotcod a gnirb d’I rosivrepus divil ym gnisimorp
.ereh saw I yhw derebmemer I litnu
.hcraes dekcilc dna rab hcraes eht otni "flowerew"
.daeh ym koohs I .sevlowerew
.pu naelc ot gniht erom enO .detsuahxe dna ,yrgnuh ,detartsurf ,demaercs I "!adatup éuQ¡" .roolf eht revo lla dna elbat eht ffo xim atijaf gnipmud dna revo ti gnippit
.desolc sdraobpuc eht gnimmals
?sdik ym erew erehw os ,xis sdrawot pu gnigde saw kcolc ehT
,samajap no tup
,ereh saw I taht won tub
I auhauhihC a sa tub
,tas dna deffins god ehT ".t'nod
.tekcop eht otni elzzum ym teg ot deganam I stnap ym ta dnuora gnison fo setunim wef a retfA
.noisiv ym gnikcolb
,godllub a ekil kool mih gnikam
.moor tnorf eht morf dellac ,dnabsuh ym ,ybriK
,nehctik eht ni sehtolc fo elip eht
auhauhihC a saw eH
,keehc eht no em dekcep
"!kcab emoc reven ot gninraw a saw etib ehT"
auhauhihC yzarc a dah esuoh siht nwonk d’I fI
ylno em retfa emoc dah tegguN yadretsey dna
.gabliam ym ni arb dna raewrednu ym deffuts I
.esuoh txen eht rof liam eht gnirehtag dna gab ym no saw I sa desucof
.degrahc dna pu dekcab I
.enohp llec ym tuo dellup I
srevoc eht deggut I sa revo dellor ybriK
.lli yltneloiv gnieb tuoba esucxe na pu gnikam
srettel eseht reviled ot gniog tsuj m'I
.snoitseuq rehtruf llatserof ot moorhtab eht otni gnihsur
,flesym ta nwod kool ot daeh ym detsiwt I .ylddo delgnit
,deilper I sa neve eciov ym peek ot tseb ym did dna
",tol a skrab gniht siht ,naM"
.ttub ym no ereht ti leef
.sdnah reh tuo dleh ehS
,tfihs ym fo tser eht hsinif t’ndluoc I wonk reh tel ot rosivrepus ym dellac dna
.liam fo gab yvaeh eht dna mih fo dloh peek ot gnilggurts
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
ekahs ot nageb sdnah yM
".em pleh ot evah uoy ,ayaT"
.revo debbacs ydaerla dah ti ecnis tik dia tsrif eht tuo llup ot rehtob t’ndid I tub
rood tnorf eht ot txen llaw eht no detnuom saw xobliam riehT
,noitisop elbatrofmoc ylegnarts a ,sruof lla ot llef I
"!redurtni uoy ,resolc yna emoc t'noD !potS"
.etihw yklim saw eye eno dna
.enohp llec ym rof esrup ym hguorht gud I
.dellac eciov s'lrig a dna
,yawa dehcrul rac ehT
.seye sih denepo dna denway eh
.roolf eht no nwod em did ti doog eht lla rof noom eht no neeb evah llew sa thgim enohp ehT
strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,evaw elttil a meht evag ,delims I
,dray ruoy otni og t’now I"
"?emoh uoy era ,moM"
,god.ecioveht ta
d'I erofeb elkna ym no gniwang saw dna rood tnorf eht otni tes palf tac a fo tuo gniraet emac god ehT  2 fo 1 traP
ezis eht no desab tub
.noitartsurf ni yks eht ta demaercs dna elzzum ym detfil I
"?yadretsey em ot od uoy did tahW"
ym ward ot deirt I
.txen pu gnimoc saw esuoh s'tegguN
?esrup ruoy tuohtiW"
.toof auhauhihC elttil eno gnipmots
.smlap ym esiurb ot hguone drah leehw gnireets eht no dednuop I dna em hguorht nar regna fo egrus hserf A
.dnuora decnalg dna
saw god a dnA .detfihsepahs I
,dluoc I sa hgih dna drah sa depmuj I
.elpuoc eht yb secnalg drawkcab lareves tuohtiw ton hguohtla
.deneppah tsuj dah tahw fo gnikniht
.gnorw saw tahw tuo erugif ot gniyrt
,dnats ot deirt dna eerf yaw ym dehsarht I
sgel kcab yldnips ym no gnicnalab fo stnemom wef a retfA
yllacitnarf os saw eh won htuom eht ta gnimaof tsomla saw tegguN
.nekops t’ndah I fi sa dias ayaT
.enab ym erew setuor railimafnU .dnuos gnippir
rab hcraes eht otni pu kcab rosruc eht teg ot deganam I hguone noos tub
".thginot eugael gnilwoB"
.daeh ym evoba gnisir smottob riahc eht neht dna elbat eht
,revo kcolb eno tsuj dekrap saw kcurt liam yM
riahc eht otni pu kcab deppoh I
.pu yawflah neve ton
.rorret a hcus si eH
,nehctik eht otni deklaw ayaT
.morf emoc dah retsnom elttil eht esuoh eht fo rood tnorf eht fo tuo emac
,demaercs tegguN "!redurtnI"
.ecnef knil niahc a dniheb morf em ta delworg bal kcalb gib A
.moC tod rettiwT fo yletal
.yawa depmuj dna depley I
.ecnef tekcip etihw a dniheb morf em ta dekrab god a
.trohs oot tsuj saw
,taorht sih otni gud ralloc ehT ".snoitseuq
.nrub dluow sllehs ym won
,semit lareves ylduol deknoh dna
.kcab detxet ayaT "?ko UR .denialpxe daD .PN"
.teerts cilbup a no dluoc namow dekan a sa ylsuoucipsnocni sa gnisserd nageb dna
".regnarts uoy ,dray ym morf yawa yats ot uoy dlot I" .dekrab god eht
retnec ffo ylthgils saw eson sih
.stac rof saw ti thguoht dah
no meht tup ot gnol oot nekat evah dluow tI
.noisivelet thgin-etal no dik a sa hctaw ot desu d’I seivom retsnom dlo eht ot kcab dekcilf dnim yM
”auhauhihC ylnedduS“ fo
;em tib d'eh retfa yadretsey eno a otni denrut d’I dna
.ti tfil ot cirbaf eht no pirg
.gnipeels dna krad saw neercs ehT
,yeH" .srettel gnireviled nageb dna yadretsey sa ecalp emas eht ni dekrap I
'remotsuc' latsop a ta tsrubtuo erom eno taht raelc neeb dah rosivrepus ym tuB
.detarbiv ydob elohw ym neht dna
.ytterp saw I dlot eb yltnatsnoc llew sa thgim I
,tneloiv t’nsaw I
.god deticxe na fo gnikrab eht saw ekops I nehw draeh rethguad reh lla suoivbo saw ti tnemmoc reh morF
.moC tod rettiwT fo yletal
,weiv otni derekcilf neercs kcol eht dna wap ym htiw ti deppat I
.nottub kcab eht dekcilc I
hteet rewol sih taht os
.etagitsevni ot deppots ro em deciton eno on tub
,keehc eht no mih dekcep
.em morf mih koot ehs sa dias namow eht ",uoy knaht ,hO"
t’nsaw ylderussa tsom I
.noitarepsed fo tuo egapbew sretnuH ditpyrC eht gnidaer retfa
"!gniklat m’I ,gnikrab ton m’I"
,em dnif dna emoh teg ot eno eht neeb dah ayaT
,kcos etihw ym fo ffuc eht otni dekaos dah doolB
"!lufdnah a hcus s'eH
.spoc eht dellac elpuoc taht erofeb
.mih gnihctac rof uoy knahT"
.god a niaga ecno flesym dnuof I
.esuoh txen eht ta ffo liam deppord I
.sehsub eht otni despalloc dna
.niks ym thguac dah etib s'tegguN ,esrow nevE
.snoitseuq wef a derewsna ev'uoy litnu toN"
,flow a ot esolc gnihtyna otni nrut ton I did ylno toN
keeW krahS detide dna
.tuo saw I elihw em rof god reh gnihctaw rof sknahT
.gnizeerf saw I fi sa rettahc hteet ym ekam ot hguone drah ekahs ot nageb ydob elohw ym tub
.renoos draug no neeb evah dluow I
retnirp eht litnu
syek eht gnisserp yb
,esolc tegguN gnihsarht eht dellup I ".ces a tsuJ"
roolf eht no flesym dnuof I erofeb gnineppah saw tahw retsiger ot emit dah ylerab I
.flac eht pu yaw eht lla ffo nrot neeb dah knuhc gib A
deeps emos pu dliub ot deganam I tub
"!nevaeh knahT" "!emoh m'I ,moM"
,suounet saw noitcennoc ehT
dluoc I sa yletaciled sA
,pil ym no dewehc I
,pil sih dnoyeb tuo kcuts
,esruoc fo ,dna ,slived ,snomed
,sgniht etalupinam ot elba gnieb ton swap ym fo melborp eht tsuj t’nsaw tI
,mrof namuh ni kcab em dnuof retal noitaxaler elcsum evissergorp fo ruoh na flaH
.dessip eb annog s'daD"
".namuh diputs ,ylsuoivbO"
.yawa enohp eht dekcut I ".ot
.ylipeels delbmum eh
nworb elap gnimoceb sder
.eralg detarepsaxe na tegguN gnivig ,rood eht tuo emac namow emas ehT
,pleh rof saelp lley ot deunitnoc I
,retnuoc nehctik eht no enohp llec ym tfel d’I erehw dettops I
.esrup ym ot txen
.ykahs erew sgel ym tub
riah ym ni delgnat dna niks erab ym ta dehctarcs sehcnarB
?yzarc gniog I saW ?em ot deklat
,liam fo lluf kcurt ym pu gnikcip retfA
depyt I ssol a tA ?thgir
.kcab ym evoba delruc taht liat niht a htiw gnola
.nepo degnab rood tnorf eht
ot dedaf mrofinu ym fo yvan eht dna wolley dna
.stod gnorw eht gnitcennoc ro enil eht gnisol ,hcuot ym deterpretnisim enohp ehT
.htiw pu emoc dluoc I noitanalpxe ylno eht saw ti tub
.klaw eht pu detrats dna ,etag eht denepo
.bmuht denrub taeh eht litnu llehs atijaf a gnippilf fo tca eht ni nezorf ,doots I
sih naht regral yllacimoc saw daeh sih ,taht fo pot nO
.niaga peelsa tsaf saw eh
.t'nod uoy taht eeS"
a teg t’ndluoc I dna ylreporp gnikrow eb ot mees t’ndid sregnif yM
.hcuoc eht no delwarps dna dekan
,dias I yllis tib a gnileeF
hteet ym dettirg I os
,smelborp ym lla evlos dluow
,muelonil eht no esahcrup rof delbbarcs swalc yM
,ezorf I .dekrab god eht
,enog saw neht dna
em ta nwod deknilb ayaT
.dessap I sa ecnef eht hguorht yliraw em gnihctaw
.airaM ,tsedlo ym morf ylper esret eht emac ",s'annairB tA"
3x3 A ".nrettaP ruoy warD" ot em gnitpmorp
,em ot txen daor eht no tlah ot dehceercs rac A
,deworc I ",ay toG" .niaga
.ot su sdeen dneirf ym revenehw
.deltrats eb t'nod"
,kcis ni dellac I gninrom txen ehT
".won enif si gnihtyrevE .eniF"
"!esuoh yM !yawa oG !yeh
.rab hcraes eht ni rosruc gniknilb eht ta derats I
,etib-rednu na dah auhauhihC nat ehT .nees reve
"!did I seY" "?em ot kaeps
.ecnalg drawkcab a em gnivig neve ton ,esuoh eht otni yawa gnipeews ,dedlocs ehs
.pets hcae htiw reivaeh dna reivaeh gnitteg
"!adreiM¡" .htaenrednu neercs eht dellif stod fo kcolb
”auhauhihC ylnedduS“   yojne esaelP
.gnilialf dna gnikrab
"?eman s’god eht s’tahW"
.roolf eht otno kcapkcab dna seohs sinnet yddum reh gniddehs
,nehctik eht otni deppets eH ".tahc ot emit oN"
.ffo mih gnittuc ,dezzub mrala yM "--ohp rO
desserd tog I retfA
,ssem eht ta denaorg
,sreward eht otni tsrifdaeh kcams ot ylno
!yawa yatS !uoy ,yeH"
.god eht ta dekool dna xobliam eht rof gnihcaer dnah ym htiw niaga deppots I
dekaerc rood tnorf ehT
,klawedis eht no yb deklaw elpoep wef a dna teerts eht ni yb dezzub srac dekrow I sA
,trid eht ni dekan tas I litnu ezis ni werg I sa
,deb fo tuo dellor dna
.gnillud dna gnidaf sroloc eht
,egassem txet gnimocni na htiw dezzub dna demihc enohp ym ,em evobA
,eson ym htiw dnuora esuom eht gnivom dna swap ym htiw draobyek eht no gnipat fo rorre dna lairt emos koot tI
,pirts a ot deworran noisiv yM
,tnessa sa taht koot I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.rof hcraes ot tahw aedi on dah I dezilaer I
,reh ta deppans I ".kcapkcab ruoy pu kcip dna hcrop eht no seohs ruoy tuP
"?god a teg ew did nehw dnA ?uoy era erehW"
",tegguN nekcihC daB"
,aidepikiW ,esruoc fo
.god eht ta derats dna ,deltrats
,wohemos ,ylnedduS
,flow a ekil adnik
,seivom dna semag suoirav morf erew stluser s'egap eht fo tser ehT
.ekahs ot gninnigeb flesym leef dluoc I dna
,yltnatropmi tsom ,sulP
.pans dna mriuqs ot gniunitnoc
.od ot tahw tuo erugif ot deirt dna trid eht ni tas I tib a nwod demlac I ecnO
.niaga namuh yllufknaht tub ,dekan dna ,eros
.tsetorp ot detrats I "--tuB"
dna "sweN dlroW flowereW"
d’I trid eht gnipiw ,enohp ym pu dekcip I
,gar a teg ot devom I
,dnuorg eht rof gnipael
.tnemssarrabme htiw detaeh ecaf yM ".esimorp I
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
,skcor fo lluf ti gnillif
.azzip daH .etal emoH
"?melborp ruoy si tahw ,ydaL"
noitciF degnaF yb dehsilbup seires seidoB gnignahC eht etorw ohw
"yporhtnacyl" neve dna
erom spets owt deganam I
.etag eht no hctac eht krow ylerab dluoc I
nepo deppop yllanif tI
gur eht no pu delruc I
"sretnuH ditpyrC"
.yaw ym no eb dna
sehtaws ni deflugne
.god eht peek dluoc ew hsiW .8rG"
"!uoy fo tnorf ni thgir m'I"
,swap ym htiw neercs eht no deraems
gnikniht saw I elihW
dehcti elkna ym no dnuow eht tub
.nepo rood eht teg ot elba eb dluow I yaw on saw ereht tub
,em ta deggurhs namow ehT ".sknaht ,enif m'I"
.pu naelc ot nageb dna
.elims a htiw kcab detxet I ",alleB"
.dezad dnuora delbmuts I
;em dnuora dnapxe ot demees nehctik elohw eht gninraw tuohtiW
,ffo ti deppals I
.yldliw gnimriuqs elihw eciov dehctip hgih a ni dekrab neht dna
.klawedis eht otno dehcrul I dna
,eerf detsiwt tegguN ".yrotirret
,tnedicni rehtruf tuohtiw emoh ti edam I
.taht naht retteb wonk uoy ,ydal gnuoY"
,emoh tog ylimaf ym eno yb enO ".dessip
.egreme ot nugeb dah nrettap A
,skooB goD wobniaR yb dehsilbup
.yzarc gnidnuos tuohtiw noitseuq ym drow ot woh aedi on dah I tub
.og tel t'ndid dna taorht sti ni wol delworg tI
.dehtuom nepo em ta gnirats staes tnorf eht ni gnittis elpuoc gnuoy dekcohs a
dluoc I taht dezilaer I dna
.kcab ym denrut d’I retfa
.god elttil eht gnitfil
",gnilrad ,gniyats toN"
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.tuo ti derugif I erofeb degnip enohp yM
.yawa ti llup ot gniyrt
.dekaeuqs palf tep ehT
.od ot tahw ediced ot gniyrt
.walc a htiw yletaciled
.ycnegreme dneirF"
,tuo dehsaw nehctik eht fo sroloc ehT
.stnap deniur ym revo em ni pu dellew regnA
”auhauhihC ylnedduS“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT    .kni fo tuo nar
,taht tuoba nettogrof d’I .desruc I
# .peels ot flesym denihw dna
'sesicrexe gnimlac' ni depyt dna
,sessik dna straeh nocitome fo wels a htiw pu dewollof ayaT ".etuc oS
,kool reh ni htmraw emos saw erehT
.tnedicni tuohtiw ffo deraor meht dniheb rac ehT
.sdnah ym ni daeh ym detser dna
?taht ot dnopser ot woH
,deltrats ,deppots I
.auhauhihC a emoceb d'I
,floWcaM boR si sihT
hcraes elgooG kciuq a taht
,esirprus ni em ta deknilb tegguN
.kcab eht no redaer tnirpregnif eht gnisu ti dekcolnu yllausu I ecnis
.enohp eht ta gnirats