,dereehc enoyrevE
.meht ekil ot mees elpoep tub srevoc yltsoM
.ratiug elbisivni na ta gnimmurts ,deksa eh
,haeY" .hpmU na teg ot hguone drah kcab mih gniwoble ,dehgual hctiM
,otni gniklaw neeb evah thgim eh taht sgniht eht lla fo gnikniht deirt hctiM
.sohcnop eht fo daetsni syesrej deroloc gniraew won saw ffats ehT
.enog yletelpmoc saw morf emac eh eno eht dna
.elbat eht fo retnec eht ni nep a fo dloh debbarg dna tuo dehcaer hctiM ,erah eht rof delangis hsoJ sA
.uoy ezingocer I .yeh ,mu
.rood eht hguorht dehsup eh ,egaruoc emos htiW
.emoh kcab og ot detnaw tsuj fo dnik eh
.llaw delit yerg a tsuJ .rood on saw ereht tub ,moorhtab eht fo edis rehto eht ot kcab tnew seye siH
.sllaw eht fo ffo gnignah sorerbmos dna sepacsdnal tresed fo serutcip erew meht dnuorA
.thginkeew a s'tI"
.egats-no yppols eb annaw t'nod I dna gnimrofrep eb ot gniog m'I .emaS"
DNOMSED ,gniyas erofeb ssik eht denruter flow eht dna elggig a derahs yehT ".evitroppus
.elbat sih sdrawot gninrut ,feiler fo hgis llams a tuo tel hctiM
"?suoivbo taht I mA"
.liatgnir eht epacse ot yltsom ,taes sih fo tuo gnitteg erofeb syawyna knird sih dehsinif eH
.thgir s'tahT !haeY" .gnola deddon dna sregnif sih deppans hctiM
,nrut ot nageb daeh sih ni sleehw ehT
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“ ,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
,tsrif dias dna dehgual aerdnA
.rood moorhtab eht hguorht deppets eh ,dnim sih no liatgnir eht htiW
.egats eht fo retnec eht ni eihciR detroppus yltsom tub slacov eht fo emos no ni denioj eH
.eihciR sdrawot denrut noitnetta siH
.mih ot tsesolc gnittis eb d'eh esruoc fo dna ,eciffo eht ni tseduol eht saw eH .liatgnir ytfeh a ,hsoJ ,rekrowoc rehto sih tas hctiM ediseB
,gniksa erofeb pis a koot ehs dna
"?thgin lla ffo elttil a neeb ev'uoY ?doog gnihtyrevE"
.ta gnitteg saw ehs tahw wenk eh tub ,yltnadnuder deksa dnomseD
.gnihtyreve roF .sknahT"
.doog leef hctiM edam ti tuoba gnihton ,rewsna evitamriffa na gnieb ti etipseD ".emitemos
.spil sih ot atiragram sih gnignirb ,dias eh ",retteb reveN"
yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw
yna dah I ezilaer t'ndid I .haeY"
.resnepsid a morf slewot fo lufdnah a debbarg eH
.rof dehsiw eh tahw tog eh gnizilaer ,seye sih desolc hctiM
.eson rieht wolb ylduol enoemos draeh eh erofeb thgirf fo kaeuqs tfos a saw erehT
.tnaruatser eht otni gnidlof nageb dna "!yadseuT ocaT"
,mU" .noitnetta sih hctac ot deirt eh tub ,xof eht rof gnikool saw eh llet dluoc hctiM
.flesmih ot thguoht hctiM ,laiceps taht t'nerew yehT
.tol gnikrap a tub gnihton yb dednuorrus gnidliub elgnis a saw tI
.dnomseD morf mih evomer saw od ot dedeen eh lla dna ,detnaw eh taht gnihtyreve gniniur saw eihciR
.edis sih ot bir a mih gnivig ,deksa liatgnir eht
.rehtegot teg elttil a tsuj s'tI .yats ot evah t'nod uoY ?thgirla s'gnihtyreve erus uoy erA"
.ytriht ni ydaer gnitteg trats ot evah ylbaborp ll'I
,deretsulF "?uoy rof stohS"
.fo tnorf ni yalp ot eihciR rof ydaer egats eht dna
.sevlesmeht ot yrc ot eerf saw llats eht ni saw reveohw dna enoyna rof moorhtab a saw ti esuaceb ,yllis saw tahT
.mets eht barg ot drawrof dehcaer eh dna
.gnihtyna flesmih redro ot emit on saw ereht ,taht fo dnuos eht dekil ylniatrec eh hguoht dna ,won yadrutaS kaetS saw tI
.kcab sih no tap a evag neht dna ,deksa eh
,deksa dna worbeye dna desiar ,nrecnoc emos htiw ,dnomseD
.taht ni detseretni yrev eb ot mees t'ndid tub ,deksa eh
"?detnaw uoy tahw toN ?yddub gnorw s'tahW"
.uoy sekil eh kniht I"
tsuj m'I ,oN" ,tuo delworg tsomla eh dna kcab deppans daeh siH
,rood wen a ees ot detcepxe eh ,moorhtab eht otni kcab tog eh nehW
.edis s'hctiM ta debbir eh nehT
.maercs a ni tuo snoitartsurf sih fo lla gnittel ,retaw eht otni delley eh ,knis eht ni daeh sih htiW
.eerf rof seunev eht otni gnitteg ekil tsuj I
,mU" ,dias dna tsaf thguoht eH
,elims a htiw detaeper ,spil reh ot ssalg reh gnidloh ,aerdnA
.eb dluow ti depoh eh sa suoiciled sa saw tI
.won noitautis sih revo lortnoc emos gnileef ,elims ediw a evag nooccar ehT
,hO" .nwod mih gniwols ,wap sih pu dleh erah ehT
,egats taht no ereht tuo og ot egaruoc eihciR evig ot eno eht neeb dah dnomseD
.egats eht rof tfel dna nooccar eht ot pu sbmuht a evag eh erofeb dnoces a rof toh gniworg elzzum ,esuap ot eihciR tog tahT
.snoisnemid hguorht latrop sih gnisu saw esle enoemos ekil ,ecaps sih fo noisavni na ekil tlef tsomla tI
.won tib elttil a rof tuo gnignah neeb tsuj ev'ew ,mU"
etisoppo rood a morf gnimoc sesion draeh eh nehw s'tahT
,snoisnemid hguorht gnippoh keewkrow eritne sih piks ot tog eh fi dalg eb dluow eh hguohT
.kcab thgir eb ll'I" .taes sih fo tuo gnitteg ,dias eh ",niaga moortser eht esu ot deen I kniht I ,yeh
.kcab thgir eb ll'I .ti tuoba yrrow t'noD .gnihtemos gnixif tsuj m'I"
.detnaw eh gnihtyreve mih evig ot gnitiaW
.tib a ffo mih looc dluow ti taht gnipoh ,ecaf sih otni retaw eht dehsalps eh nehT
.seye sih dellor hctiM dna taht ta dehgual puorg ehT ".eerf
.don evitamriffa na evag eh dna deksa ehs
.esnes hcum ekam t'ndid tahT
.flesmih thgin lla yrc ot detnaw eh ekil gnileef neeb d'eh nehw toN
.detnaw eh tahw gnitaeper tpek eh ,dnim sih nI
.llaw delit a won saw ti ees ot ylno
.uoy sekil eh kniht I"
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.kcep ralimis a denruter tub ,dehsulb dnomseD
.noisnet eht esae ot demees tahT ".laiceps
.etad a saw ti thguoht d'eh ,yadseuT ocaT rof tuo og ot mih deksa dah ,dnomseD ,rekrowoc sih nehW
,satinuaJ eht ot dehcatta saw tnaruatser rehtona ekil dednuos tI .dekrep srae
,won mih htiw ytinutroppo sih evah dluoc eh thguoht eh hguoht dna ,desufnoc demees dnomseD
.uoy sekil eh kniht I"
.eldnah eht barg ot tuo wap sih gnihcaer ,ti sdrawot spets kciuq koot eH
mih morf ssorca elbat a ta gnittis xof ssorc a saw erehT
.potretnuoc etinarg a ni sknis owt erew ereht dna ,kcalb erew ,meht fo eerht ,sllats eht
,dias dna iaT iaM neknard flah sih debbarg hctiM "?taht saw tahW"
,etoyoC triD yb ”yadseuT ocaT“
"?kniht uoy t'nod ,hcterts a fo tib elttiL
,dias dna daeh sih koohs ,hctiM ta kool ot pu daeh sih gninrut ,eihciR
"?srab emas eht ot og ew kniht I
.tuoba gniklat neeb evah thgim eh ohw ees ot niatruc eht dniheb morf daeh sih ekop eihciR gnihctaw ,dehgual hctiM
,og erah eht tel eh erofeb tub ,deddon nooccar ehT
.pit a stnaw enoemoS"
.ti od nac I kniht t'nod I"
.ssetsoh eht ot kcab regap eht gnignirb ,ni klaw ot tsal saw hctiM
.redluohs s'nooccar eht otno llaf sraet emos gnittel ,guh thgit a otni hctiM dellup eihciR .egatskcab tem owt eht ,dehsinif d'yeht nehW
,dias dna ni denael eh ,tfel erah eht erofeB
.mih rof wap a pu deppilf dna mih deciton xof eht erofeb noisufnoc ni worbeye sih dekcoc eH
"!kcul em hsiW" .taes sih fo tuo gnitteg ,dias eh
.bos rehtona otni dekaorc taht hgual a gnivig
"?thgir ,noos pu og ot evah uoy ,eihciR ,mU !haey oS"
.evitroppus yrev s'eH .thgin yreve tsomla tuo gnignah neeb ev'eW
.gnihton saw ereht tub
.yrd ruf sih depiw dna ,resnepsid eht morf slewot repap emos debbarg
.kcab gnidlof srae
,xof munitalp a saw mra s'dnomseD dnuora depparW
.tsiwt a ti gnivig dna ti fo dloh gnibbarg
.keehc eht no ssik a mih gnivig ,dneirfyob sih sdrawot denrut neht dna deddon xof ehT
.sllaw eht gnola gnignah sepacsdnal tresed dna ,sorerbmos ,sgalf nacixeM htiw tem saw eh ,yletaidemmI
.emit yreve mih emocrevo dluow ysuolaej fo gnap a dna ,enipluv eht ot gnivom tpek seye siH
.taht ekil gnihtyna stnaw eh fi onnud I .sdneirf tsuj er'ew ,haN" .elzzum sih no elims dessarrabme eht yawa epiw t'ndluoc tub ,daeh sih koohs flow ehT ".uoy
",dnuora uoy ees ll'I .og ot tog ,syawynA .haey ,haeY—" "—
",sknahT .pu thguac tog tsomlA !thgir s'tahT" .nwod dna pu gniddon erofeb ,emit eht ta decnalg eH
,dessarrabme leef ot ecnahc a meht evig neve t'ndid hctiM tub ,hsulb a derahs owt ehT
.snoisnemid hguorht gnirednaw gniyalp saw eh emag tahw gnirednow
.nwod gnihtemos gnittoj nageb dna flesmih sdrawot nikpan a dellup eH
".esaelp ,em rof retaw a tsuJ
.neht dna won yreve hctiM ta elims ot dnuora kcab gninrut
,bonkrood eht sdrawot dehcaer eh ,ylsuoituaC
.mih morf ssorca rood on saw erehT
.rewsna ot eno eht saw flow ehT
?yadsruhT iahT eb ti dluoW
.dnuorg eht no toof sih gnipmots erofeb ytpme erew sllats eht lla erus edam eh ,mih dniheb gnikooL
,gnihtyna yas dluoc eh erofeB
.kcab dellac eciov railimaf a
.desufnoc elttil a ,rehtona eno ot sdaeh rieht denrut eihciR dna dnomseD
.yllufhsab ti dehctarcs eh dna daeh sih fo kcab eht ot tnew wap A ".doom
.llats eht morf gnimoc srepmihw teiuq eht erongi t'ndluoc eh tub ,rood siht fo edis rehto eht no tsuj saw detnaw eh gnihtyrevE
.ti ta derats dna morf emac eh rood eht ot kcab denrut hctiM
”yadseuT ocaT“   yojne esaelP
.retal setunim elpuoc a moorhtab eht tfel eihciR dna hctiM
,gnirettum dna don flah a gnivig
.llew sa naicisum detnelat a yltnerappa dna ,ynnuf ,ymrahc ,lufituaeb saw eihciR
.elpuoc eht otni gninael
,gniyas erofeb ti fo tser eht dehsinif dna spil sih ot knird eht deppit eH
.ecnamrofrep ruoy dekil yllaer ,flow eht ,srekrowoc ym fo eno kniht I ,yllautcA
.nruter ni eno gnitteg ,flow eht ot kcep a evag eH
.nooccar eht ta evaw ot pu tnew rehto eht elihw s'flow eht dnuora depparw mra eno dah eH
.erofeb semit fo sderdnuh enola decitcarp d'eh taht sgnos evol yseehc eht lla saw ti dalg saw hctiM
.sknahT .em rof iaT iaM a tsuJ"
.gnola lla taht wonk ot desoppus saw eh fi sa ,dias eh ",yadsruhT tsurC nihT
,dias dna aera gninid eht sdrawot xof eht detniop eh ,thgir ekam ot gniht tsal eno llits saw ereht gniwonK
.hsoJ ot denrut neht dna
.smoorhtab eht ot yawflah ydaerla saw hctiM tub ,puorg eht morf hgual rehtona gnitteg , gnihtemos dias hsoJ ".kcab
.esrow yna teg t'ndluoc thgin sihT
.enoyreve fo tnorf ni elims a ekaf ot gniyrt selcsum sih deniarts ti tub ,nisiar ruos a ekil kool ot ton tseb sih did eH
.suoiciled yletulosba dekool taht atiragram demmir tlas a htiw
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
.revo mih gnivaw ,wap sih desiar eihciR ,erehT
EIHCIR .srekrowoc sih fo lla htiw yliddig yawa gnittahc
",mp7 dnuora pu og I ,haeY"
daw a dah eH .llats sih denepo xof eht erofeb gnilffuhs emos draeh eh ,rood eht fo edis rehto eht nO "?eihciR"
.edisni dekaep dna nikpan eht dedlofnu eh sa tuhs depsalc elzzum sih tub ,gnihtemos yas ot dekool eH .dehctiwt sreksihw s'enipal eht ,desufnoC
.setadpu erutuf rof ykS eulB no
,gniksa ,knis eht tsniaga flesmih denael hctiM
",kraL ehT ot og yllausu I .ebyam
,deksa ,elbat eht otni gninael ,hctiM
.thgiarts ruoh na rof deyalp owt ehT
.eldnah eht no wap sih decalp dna ti sdrawot deklaw eh ,ylsuoiruC
.niaga sbos otni elbmurc ot ydaer demees eh dna ykahs erew sdrow siH ".bmud
,yerg erew llaw eht no selit ehT
,edisrehto eht ot revo dekool hctiM
.syawyna rood eht nepo dehsup tub ,depmuts deniamer eh ,htaerb peed a gnikaT
.dnuora denrut dna bonkrood eht fo og tel eh ,hgis a htiW
,detpurretni eihciR ",sdneirf tsuj er'eW .on ,ahah
.eniuneg oot elttil a tsuj demees taht eno ,elims a derahs eihciR dna dnomseD
".hcnuh a ti llac tsuJ"
"?ereht ni ekoc fo spmub gniod uoy er'tahW ?niagA"
.yalp ot nageb eh ,naicisum rehtona morf ratiug a gniworrob dna egats no gniog ,nehT
",gnihtemos ro eivom a hctaw dluoc ew ro sratiug ym fo emos uoy wohs nac I .tuo gnah dluoc eW .emitemos ecalp ym ot revo emoc nac uoy ebyaM .dnomseD ,yas
.ti deciton eno on ,yllufknahT
,dias dna elggig a tuo tel ehS
.detnaw eh tahw t'nsi sihT .kcab hsiw sih ekat ot yaw on saw erehT
.doom doog a ni er'uoY"
.rehtegot t'nera eihciR dna dnomseD .rehtegot t'nera eihciR dna dnomseD .rehtegot t'nera eihciR dna dnomseD
.suoires gnihtyna t'nsaw siht taht epoh llams a ,noitasrevnoc eht ot dekcilf srae s'nooccar ehT
,dedda eh ,elims yls a pu gnikrow ,nehT ".dnomseD
.cisum yalp dluoc eh taht detseretni mees flow eht did ecno reveN
.llaw eht no regnol on erew snoitaroced ykcat dna sgalf nacixeM eht fo enon ,hguoht ,s'atinauJ eht ot ralimis saw tI
.mih gnidnuorrus staob fo serutcip ni derevoc saw tnaruatser eht ,mih erofeB
,deksa dna did aerdnA tub ,egnahcxe eht deciton t'ndah hsoJ
.tfel dna deddon eh nehT
.yart azzip a gniyrrac retiaw a fo yaw eht fo tuo deppets nooccar ehT
"?mih gnitcepxe uoy ereW ?emussa I ,dehsams gnitteg emoh ta s'eh sseug I ,hgU
.ydaer gnitteg trats attog I !thgir s'taht ,toohs hO"
.sknaht tnelis a gnivig erofeb naelc elzzum sih dehsurb dna nikpan a debbarg eH
.thgir sih morf gnimoc tnaruatser a fo sdnuos eht gniciton
,mu ,haeY" .ti gnikahs erofeb daeh sih deddon hctiM
.elzzum sih ta yawa gnipiw ,wap sih ni repap teliot fo
.mih rof ratiug a gniyalp denoitom eH ".flesym
.eciffo eht fo tser eht htiw gnola gniggat eb ot tnaw yllaer t'ndid nooccar ehT
"?teem dnomseD dna uoy did woh ,oS"
,dias dna kniw a mih evag ,elbat eht no swoble reh gnittup ,aerdnA
,dias eh ",ssem gnikcuf a hcus ekil kool I yrroS .snaf
.xof eht ot noitnetta sih denrut tub ,niaga deddon dnomseD "?emitemos uoy rof gnihtemos yalp nac I ebyam rO ?ebyaM" ,deksa ,elims a htiw ni gninael ,hctiM
.elbat eht no ti gnittis erofeb kcab ssalg eritne eht gnippit tsomla ,ti fo pis gnol a koot eH
.mih htiw enoemos dah ydaerla flow eht taht wonk t'ndid eh ,hguoht oseroM
EIHCIR ,dias xof eht erofeb ,dehgual dna rehtona eno ot kool a evag eihciR dna dnomseD "?yadsruhT azzip
,dias dna sdrow reh ffo devaw ,ti deretsiger yldrah gnivah ,hctiM "?he ,laiceps artxE"
erofeb ereh neeb t'ndah rood sihT .eurt t'nsaw taht ,oN
.ediw elims ,dias erah eht
.ecalp eht gnirettil sleehw pihs nedoow dna sten htiw llaw a tsniaga gnignah nilraM citsalp a saw erehT
.yllufeelg dias eh ",dnoces a enog ylno erew uoy ,oN"
.tnaruatser eht ta mih tuoba lla gnikool
.eihciR ot nrut ezag reh was eh erofeb ,elzzum sih nepo ot tuoba saw hctiM
.retiaw eht rof thgir dna tfel gnikool dnuora deppilf neht dna detuohs yllacitcarp eh
"?gniyalp uoy sgnos tahW
",yug ym s'tahT !haeY"
.daehrevo srekaeps eht no gniyalp noidrocca na htiw tem saw eh ,yltnatsnI
.meht fo lla yalp ot woh gniwonk hctiM
.mih ta gnirats won saw elbat eht ta enoyreve gniciton ,flesmih thguac eH "—
.gniddik t'nsaw retiaw eht ,woW"
.noitartsurf sih ni dnuora denrut tog ev'tsum eh dnoces a rof thguoht eh dna ,llaw delit a tsuj saw tI
?yadsruhT tsurC nihT ti dellac lla uoy kniht I"
,tuo dellac hctiM ,elbat eht morf yawa pets a teg dluoc eh erofeB
.dnomseD ot txen elbat eht ta gnittis saw ,syawla sa ,eihciR
,haeY" HCTIM .liatgnir eht sdrawot nworf a evag hctiM dna ,ylhsipeehs daeh sih dekcud eihciR
,yllufhsab deksa eh dna ,knip fo edahs thgils a denrut elzzum s'xof ehT ".uoy
,dnah ni telbat a htiw elbat eht dehcaorppa erah hsikniwt A
.ffo ti yalp ot gniyrt ,dias eh ",thginot tuo emoc ot detnaw ev'dluow eh thguoht tsuj I sseug I ,oN"
",pu dexim lla uoy tog s'kroW
ta tsuj erew ew —redro t'ndid I"
?yalp uoy t'nod ,yeH"
.noitautis siht ni saw eh taht deyonna ,nam reggib eht morf yawa taes sih dehcni eH
.evitcepsrep emos dedeen tsuJ .syug taht tuoba yrros ,haeY"
.llats a morf gnimoc gnilffins fo dnuos eht thguac hctiM ,dluoc eh erofeB
.hctiM dna mih htob rof stohs gnitteg hsoJ ,elbat rieht ot tog retiaw ehT
.evisneffo no deredrob taht sohcnop gnikool suolucidir gniraew erew ffats eht llA
.hgis llams a tuo tel dna iaT iaM sih fo pis a koot nooccar eht ,laiceps t'nerew taht sgniht fo cipot eht nO
,eton elgnis a elbmuf t'ndid xof ehT
.ti fo tuo flesmih gnivael yltsom hctiM htiw snoitasrevnoc thgil ot denrut elbat ehT
HCTIM .elbat eht morf hgual denrecnoc llams a gnitteg ,dias eh
.enohp sih tuo dellup dna psag a tuo tel xof ehT
.niaga kraL ehT ot og ot deen reven d'eh ,llew tnew thginot fI
"?…oooooooowt uoy erA" ,deksa ylluferac neht dna deddon hctiM ".ereht
.enod d'eh tahw rof ytliug elttil a gnileef llits ,nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon hctiM
.mih dnuora klaw ot gniyrt ,dias eh
.ria eht otni tsif a depmup eh neht dna ,esirprus ni pu detfil daeh s'liatgnir ehT ".tohs a rof uoy nioj thgim I kniht I ,wonk uoY"
.rewsna eht fo erus saw eh hguoht neve "?hsoJ s'erehW"
.noitcerid sih ni skeep gnikaens saw erah eht ees dluoc eH
.tnaruatser eht otni gnippets ,syawyna drawrof dehsup hctiM
.tib elttil a ,ekil ,nI"
.puorg eht htiw gnidnats knim a ot yas eihciR draeh eh
"?neves fo ytrap ,hctiM"
.mih morf ssorca yltcerid detiaw rood a ,ydaerlA
.siht xif ot od dluoc eh tahw tuoba drah gnikniht ,trohs flesmih tuc hctiM "—I ,oN"
etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
"?wohs a rof ydaer uoY !yddub yeH"
.ylsuoiruc deksa eh "?gnihtyna ssim I did ,yeH"
EIHCIR .keehc s'flow eht ot kcep a evag dna ni denael eh sa tuo thguoht taht deffuns eihciR
.ereht tuo taerg did uoY"
.ecnetnes sih ni doog drow eht tuoba dnim sih no gnihtemos ,taht ta detsiwt elzzum s'dnomseD ".lla
.gnipag tfel saw wam sih dna daeh sih fo kcab eht no dedlof srae s'nooccar ehT
,sgnos pop fo hcnub a ffo tsil ot nageb eH ".meht
troppus rof dneirfyob sih tsniaga denael xof munitalp ehT .thgir hO
.sknis eht sdrawot thgiarts gniklaw ,rood eht nepo tsrub yllacitcarp eH
.xof eht ta gnilims dna pu gninrut ,deksa eh "?ruoh flah rehtona ni pu gniog s'eihciR
",tluaf ym saw tahT .yrros ,oN" .nwod elzzum sih gnippid ,dnoces a rof lufhsab dekool hctiM
.noitcerid sih lwocs llams a evag eh dna ,kcud srae s'hctiM edam tI
,deksa ,elims yrw a htiw ,aerdnA
zzzzB .mih rof lla meht yalp ot detnaw eh ,hturt nI
.llirG dna raB s'atinauJ fo edistuo flesmih ot delbmurg hctiM etoyoC triD yB
.deraeppa dah rood on tub
,dias dna wap sih desiar eihciR
.gnisuap dna eldnah eht fo dloh gnibbarg ,rood wen eht ot deklaw eH
.mih fo tnorf ni atiragram eht ta detniop ,drawrof gninael ,dnomseD
,gniyas erofeb knird reh fo pis a koot aerdnA
.ot emoh og ot sbuc tog I nehw stohs gniod ton m'I
,syawynA .haey ,haeY" ,gniyas ylevissimsid daeh sih deddon hctiM ".uoy
.dnomseD ot txen gnittis llits saw xof ehT
.slanac cinoci s'ecineV fo serutcip htiw gnola ,erehwyreve sgalf nailatI erew erehT
.ni deklaw eh emit tsrif eht ekil dekool denigami eh tahw ,tsael ta ,emas eht dekool gnihtyrevE
.elbat eht ot noitnetta sih denrut neht ,ti ta desufnoc dekool eH
.knird sih fo pis a koot dna pil sih ot ssalg eht tup eh ,ylluferaC
.yllufworros daeh sih koohs neht tub ,tsrif ta nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon eihciR
.mih ediseb liatgnir tnesba na gniciton ,taes sih koot hctiM
HCTIM .ogol llabtoof s'kciK hgiH eht fo kcalb dna egnaro eht dezingocer eH .sgalf dna strihs deroloc maet dna raeg strops tnereffid htiw decalper won erew yeht ,daetsnI
.sretroppus tseggib sih fo eno morf ffo mih tuc dah ylhsifles eh dna
,ylduol dehgual neht dna hctiM ot kool driew a evag hsoJ
"?rehto hcae gniees neeb owt uoy evah gnol woH"
.eybdoog evaw a mih evag tsuj eh
.llaw a tsuj deniamer llaw delit yerg eht ,did eh tahw rettam oN
.mih morf ssorca rehto hcae dloh dna egdun lufyalp flow dna xof eht gnihctaw yltsom saw noitnetta siH
".ffutS toH ta er'eW .yadsendeW gniW s'ti ,orB" ,dias dna woble na htiw mih ta debbaj eh ,dluow liatgnir eht ekil ,nehT ".yadot citceh neeb ev'tsum skoob esoht ,zeeJ ?s'atinauJ"
.retiaw eht eye ot kcab gninrut erofeb dias eh ",gnihtoN"
.yawa dellup eh sa seye sih gnihsurb
.mih gniwollof elggig llams a ,ylkciuq dnuora nups eh nehT ".uoy
.puorg eht ot dias eh ",ydaer si elbat ruo kniht I ,mU" HCTIM .wap sih ni regap gnimmuh eht ta nwod dekool hctiM
.knird sih detpecca eh sa ylevissimsid dias hctiM ",erus ,hgu ,hO"
.moortser eht rof tfel eh nehw ti detnaw eh hcum woh ,atiragram eht tuoba thguoht hctiM
,niaga mih deppots bos tfos A
"?erofeb taht denoitnem uoy kniht I
.retiaw erah eht otni thgir nar tsomla eh taht esarhp eht no desucof os saw eH
"?uoy t'nera ,tib elttil a ni pu og annog er'uoY ?gnorw s'tahW"
.moortser eht sdrawot deklaw dna taes sih morf tog eh nehT
gnirednow saw I .eno eht s'taht ,haeY"
.pis a ekat dluohs uoy ebyaM"
,deksa dna aerdnA ot revo dekool eH
.gnihtyna laever ot ton suoituac ,wols erew sdrow siH
.uoy rof laiceps artxe edam saw eno siht erus edam I"
.gnidaelp saw eh ekil dnuos ot ton tseb sih gniyrt ,dias eh
,hctiM sdrawot ylthgils ylno daeh sih denrut flow ehT
.emitemos taht od dluohs eW .erus ,haeY"
,pu til seye s'xof ehT
.bonk eht denrut eH
.tuo detsrub liatgnir eht "?enoyreve rof stohs fo dnuor a tuob woH" HSOJ
.ylduol yarps retaw gnittel ,tecuaf eht fo seldnah eht denrut hctiM
.xof eht morf guh gnitrap erom eno htiw tfel neht dna dias eh ",tsaf yllaer moorhtab eht ot nur attog tsuj I ?su htiw tis uoy t'nod yhW"
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,gnittes eht tuoba desufnoc llitS
tuoba smra sih evaw ot gniunitnoc ,dehgual hsoJ
,dias eh ",uoy tuohtiw siht enod evah dluoc I kniht t'nod I
erom ecno knis eht ot mih del ytisoiruc sih tub
.elcric eht morf yawa toof drawkwa elbatrofmocnu na tpek hctiM
.tsrif taes a gnikat nooccar eht ,elbat a ot del erew yehT
.ereht dna ereh gnittahc neeb tsuj ev'ew dna rab a ta yalp mih was I
.gnis dna ratiug eht yalp I .ffuts olos emos tsuj ,hO" ,dias dna
.allef eihciR siht ,oS"
.edis rehto eht no gniltsub llits tnaruatser eht raeh dluoc eH
.egassem txet wen eno deviecer dah eh ,dehsinif neve dah yadseuT ocaT erofeB
,elims llams a htiw hctiM ta dekool erah ehT ".egats-
.mih morf ssorca yltcerid tops eht dekcip dah eihciR dna dnomseD ,kcul sih tsuj dnA
.sreksihw nwo sih morf gnignah tlas eht gnileef won ,depsag eh erofeb ,noitom eht ta worbeye na desiar hctiM .yletilop sreksihw sih ta epiw ot nageb eh neht dna deciton ,mih morf ssorca ,eihciR
,ti sdrawot deppets eh ,ylsuoiruC
.elzzum sih revo ti nar dna ,meht otni retaw depoocs ,pu swap sih thguorb tsuJ .yltnereffid esohc tub niaga lley ot gnikniht ,ni daeh sih deppid eH
",thgirla eb lliw gnihtyrevE .em tsurT .enif s'ti ,oN"
.moortser eht ot rood eht gnivael ton seye ,dias eh
.raeh ot tnaw dluow eh taht sgnos evol yllis eht fo yna yalp dluoc hctiM
"!yddub ,kcul fo tseB"
.saw eh ohw aedi on dah xof eht ,eihciR gniteem dnomseD tuohtiW
,dias ,aerdnA ,knim eht ",looc os s'tahT"
.mih tsap gniklaw ,dias hctiM
.esac eht t'nsaw taht tub ,yadirF nekcihC deirF rof deticxe saw eh ,ylgnittimdA
.mih detpurretni aerdnA erofeb moorhtab eht sdrawot pets elgnis a tog eh ,niaga pu gnitteG
.edis eht ot ylthgils daeh sih dekcoc eh dna
.enohp sih tuo dellup eh dna ,pu dekrep srae s'eihciR
,hO" EIHCIR .pu tnew srae s'xof eht litnu gnah trap tsal taht tel eH
.llats eht fo edis eht tsniaga gniknuls dna wap sih gnivaw ,dias eh ",gniyrt rehtob I yhw wonk neve t'nod I
daD regdaB yldduC ,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
.mih dniheb gnihton saw ereht ,esirprus on ot tub ,hguorht deppets tsuj eh rood eht ot kcab daeh sih denrut eH
.doog yrev er'uoY .eb ot ton drah s'tI"
.yrenecs fo egnahc eht ta derraj elttil a llits ,yltsedom dias eh ",sgnos wef a wonk I .thgirla m'I ,haeY" .erutseg ralimis a gnikam ,daeh sih deddon hctiM
.moortser eht fo elddim eht otni gnippets ,deksa eh "?thgirla gnihtyrevE"
.og attog xof tahT
.taht ekil t'ndid hctiM
"?thgir ,taerg s'eH"
.smoorhtab eht sdrawot deklaw dna flesmih desucxe eh ",moortser eht esu annog tsuj m'I"
.thgir siht tog eh taht saw ti tnatropmi woh dnatsrednu t'ndluoc yehT
,elbat rehto eht ta gnittis xof ssorc eht ,srekrowoc sih ,ffats gnitiaw eht :emas eht erew sgniht tsoM
.taes sih fo tuo gnitteg ylkciuq ,dias eh ",rednimer eht rof sknahT
,flesmih ot derettum hctiM ,gnilbmurG
?hsoJ" AERDNA ,deksa dna noisufnoc ni edis eht ot daeh reh dekcoc diletsum ehT
.flesmih desucxe dna daeh sih deddon eh ,niaga smoorhtab eht ot revo gnikool ,nehT
.1202 fo
.ereht t'nsaw ti taht
.lla si suoiruc saw tsuj ,ahaH .doog hO"
.regnol ekil sleef tI"
.bmud tsuj m'I .tluaf ruoy ton s'tI"
.thgin lla no dah eh taht elims emas taht gniraew llits ,daeh sih koohs eihciR
,etoyoC triD yb ”yadseuT ocaT“ saw sihT
.enola ereht pu og ot evah t'nod uoY .yddub ,yeH"
.mih rof gnitiaw rood eht saw moorhtab eht fo edis etisoppo eht tA
.enod tsuj d'eh tahw gnizilaer ,daeh sih koohs hctiM ".em
.meht derongi tsuj hctiM tub ,srekrowoc sih neewteb derahs srumrum erew erehT ".kcab
.gniliec eht dnuora gnurts erew der dna ,etihw ,neerg fo snobbiR
,dias dna pot eht ot detniop eh ,puorg eht pu dloh ot gnitnaw toN
,egats eht sdrawot kcab denrut daeh s'dnomseD ".taht
.yadnuS ihsuS ot drawrof neve ebyam ro yadrutaS kaetS ot kcab gniog saw eh fi dnoces a rof derednow eH
.od ot dah eh tahw od ot egaruoc eht dnuof nooccar eht erofeb dnoces a rof ecnelis ni doots yehT
",enif si gnihtyrevE"
.hguorht dehsup neht dna ylluferac hsiw sih tuoba gnikniht ,rood moorhtab eht fo dloh debbarg eH
,deksa dna worb reh deworruf aerdnA
.llirg dna rab strops a fo dnarb lanoitan eht ,eman eht dezingocer hctiM
.xof eht ot revo gnitniop ,dias eh ",sgniht wef a uoy hcaet mih evah dluohs uoy ebyaM .yug siht sa doog sa ton er'uoy teb I" .loof a ekil
.mih sdrawot wap a gnisiar eihciR htiw ,elbat sih was eh nehw s'tahT
.ylduol demialcxe eh ",etirovaf ym s'eno taht ,hO" .tohs a gnikat retfa drawrof denael hsoJ
.elims hsilived sih kcab dloh ot gniyrt ,dias eh
,mih looc ti tel eH
.flesym tib elttil a yalp nac I wonk uoY .cisum ekil uoy ,dnomseD ,oS" ,ylkciuq dias hctiM ,kaeps mih tel dluoc eh erofeB
.esruoc —gnikcuf —fO .yadirF spihC dna hsiF"
.dias eh ",hcnuh a ti llac ,tsuJ"
.noisufnoc ni worb sih deworruf dna ,eciov eht dezingocer hctiM
.dnomseD ot txen detaes llits saw eihciR ,esirprus sih oT ".esruoc
"?emitemos rehtegot yalp dluoc eihciR dna uoy ebyaM .looc s'tahT ?haey hO"
,tuo ti yalp dna yadsendeW gniW ot kcab og ot tsuj thguoht eh ,tsrif tA
.kcab dedlof srae
,ecaf sih gnihsaw dna retaw eht no gninrut etaercer ot gniyrt ,knis eht ot deklaw eH
.tsenoh eb ot ,detnaw eh tahw ton saw thgin elohw sihT
.saw siht enisiuc tahw togrof enoyna esac ni ,elbat hcae fo retnec eht ni galf a neve saw erehT
.emit siht knis eht ot og ot deen neve t'ndid tub ,moorhtab eht otni deklaw eh ,niagA
"?pu og uoy od nehw
.kcab devaw dna delims eH
,dias eh ",yadseuT ocaT rof uoy fo lla htiw tuo emoc em gnittel rof sknahT
,morf emac eh rood eht sdrawot denrut eh ,elims a htiw ,nehT
.od ot evah d'eh tahw wenk eH .gnihtyreve gniniur xof nmad taht saw tI
.dias eh ",niaga moorhtab eht otni pid attog I .em hguorht gniog yllaer si atiragram siht ,wonk uoY"
.flesmih ratiug eht gniyalp ta doog ytterp yllautca saw eH
,nwod dna pu gniddon ,wap a tuo dleh hctiM ".worromot krow ta uoy ees ll'eW
.hguorht deppets dna moortser eht fo edis rehto eht ot deklaw tsuj eh ,taht gnirongI
.don wols a ni nwod dna pu tnew daeh s'dnomseD
.ekat ot mih rof nikpan eht pu dleh eh
",iaT iaM ruoy dnA"
.elzzum s'enipal eht no truh eht retsiger ot erac neve t'ndid eH
"?pu tog I nehw satinauJ egnahc yeht diD"
.tnemredliweb nwo s'nooccar eht ta desufnoc yltsom ,mih no seye dah enoyrevE
.taes sih ekat ot revo deklaw neht dna kcab devaw ylsuoituac hctiM
.semit rehto eht lla moorhtab siht edisni esle enoyna neeb reven d'erehT .desuap eH
.saw nooccar eht sa desufnoc sa tsuj dekool eh ,tuo deppets eh nehW
.eromyna mih htiw gnituo siht ta eb ot mih tnaw t'ndid yletinifed eh dna hsoJ ekil ton did eH
won gniciton ylno ,morf emac eh rood eht ot kcab denrut daeh siH
"?thgir ,won htnom a tsomlA .onnud I ,hO" DNOMSED
s'ti oS" ,deksa eh nehT
.em ees ot ereh s’ydoboN
"?thgirima ,su rof eroM" .ffo ti dehgual tsuj hsoJ tub ,stohs fo reffo eht pu nekat dah dnomseD ylnO ".sknahT
,pu tnew sworbeye reH ".pit
.tohs dnoces sih gnihsinif ydaerla ,mih ot txen gnittis saw hsoJ ,sih ot kcab tog eh nehW
.eihciR tem reven evah ot dnomseD rof naht erom gnihton detnaw hctiM
.edis eht ot pets a koot eh sa flesmih desucxe retiaw eht ",yrros ,spoohW"
AERDNA .mih rof gniog gnihtyreve dah eH
.puorg eht ta dnuora gnikool ,elbat eht no knird eht tup eH
.iaT iaM siht tnaw t'ndid eh ,hguoht yllacificepS
,ekahs kciuq a gnivig erofeb daeh sih gniddon ,atiragram sih ta nwod dekool hctiM
.gnituo krow a fo trap a saw noitativni sih taht ezilaer t'ndid eh ,gnol os rof flow eht no dehsurc dah eH
.mih ecaf ot denrut dna deciton hsoJ
.mih dniheb lwob eht otni daw eht gniworht ,deksa eh "?uoy wonk I oD"
"?uoy rof detrats teg I nac tahW"
.rood moorhtab eht rof decar yeht sa nepo eht otni tuo mih gnicrof ,mih dessap dehsup tseug A .desufnoc dnuora deklaw eh sa flesmih ot derepsihw nooccar eht "?kcuf ehT"
,dad regdab yldduc ruoy ,seirraH loS si sihT  .goD
.repsihw a ni dezigolopa eh ",yrros os m'I"
.dnomseD ot detniop saw eson reH ".allef
,daeh sih denrut hctiM ".ytriht
"?thgir ,thginot gniyalp er'uoY .eciov ruoy dezingocer I .haey
.xof eht ot denrut yllufhsab eh dna ,knip fo edahs thgils a denrut srae s'dnomseD
"?yalp uoy od cisum fo tros tahw oS"
,levon a gnitirw si ,enilno elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw
.tsirw sih fo kcab eht htiw ecaf sih no ruf dettam eht pu naelc ot gniyrt ,nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon eihciR
,gniyas erofeb hgis gnol a tuo tel eh ,ni gnihtaerB
.retaw eht no denrut eh dna
.yawa deklaw eh sa eralg a htiw eihciR dewollof eh dna tsiwt elzzum s'nooccar eht edam tI
.retiaw eht ot dias eh ",reilrae siht deppord uoy kniht I ,hu ,yeH"
.reilrae morf noitartsurf eht dah regnol on eh tub ,niaga retaw eht otni lley ot deirt eh ,saw ti sa yfoog sA
.taes sih otni elttil a gniknis erofeb reh ot denrut flow ehT
,deksa dna elbat sih ot kcab tog eh
.t'nsaw ereht taht erus saw eh tub
.dnomseD si eman siH
.niaga nooccar eht otni gnibbur ,emas eht deniamer hsoJ
.sllaw eht no ailager strops eht lla htiw tnaruatser ffutS toH a yletinifed saw ti tuB
,dias hctiM ,elkcuhc a htiw ,nehT
.hguorht emac eh eno eht fo
.mih dniheb gniggaw liat yhsub sih raeh yllacitcarp dluoc eh dna
.revo ti dekool dna elbat eht fo retnec eht morf unem knird llams eht debbarg nooccar eht
.nalp sih mih gnillet ,dnoces a rof srekrowoc sih yb deppots ylno hctiM .sraet sih edih ot hguone elzzum sih pu denaelc dah xof ehT
.eno on rof srevoc diputs yalp si od I llA"
.ssalg atiragram eht fo mir detlas eht ta gnikool ,ffo flesmih tuc eh "—
.erusserp fo tnuoma tsethgils eht ta yaw gnivig ,dekcolnu saw tI
.srewsna llams evag tsuj nooccar eht ,gnihtemos no tupni sih rof deksa saw eh nehW
.laiceps ti ekam did eH