”. suolucidir leef I tuB“
”!no ti evah uoy ,hsog ym ,hO“ !depsag nehT
,lleW ?etelhta retniw a neeb ev’dluoc I kniht … hah … ymmE ,yeH“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.dewollaws knuks ehT ” … syadiloh eht … os
”.elbaraew gnihtemoS“
,htaerb a tuo welb esuom ehT
.trops taht ni serah dna stibbar ynam os ees uoy yhw ylbaborP“
,ni gniggid erofeB
?gnidlofnu saw thgin eht yaw ehT
.fracs gniliart a ekil gniwollib liat derruf-nomannic
”.yletinifeD .haey ,hO“ ”?si tI“
,wons sa etihw sa ruf
,dnuora ylimaf evah t’nod I .ynapmoc ruoy rof dalg os m’I“ .dewob aivodleS ”.taht fo tbuod on ev’I“
.rood eht gnisolc dna ni gnilggirw ,dias ehs
”?pu taht ekil gnihtemos ekam I dluoC“ ”?yllaeR“
.seenk sti no saw edisyrtnuoc eht ekil
.s’eineeuQ ta devirra yehT
,tnegnat a reted ot gniyrt ,dias eh ”,eruS“
,mih ot dehctal d’ehs ,esuom leek neve ,yhs eht yb nekat yletaidemmI
”esuoM .T dleiF“ yb ”reiT kcosliaT“
.tlebtaes reh deruces eilrahC ”. … sgel esoht dna tahT“
.deriter yeht nehw mraf s’elcnu dna tnua reh tirehni ot eud saw ehS
.dedeeccus d’ehS
,esuoh s’eilrahC erofeb thgir daor levarg eht ni dneb a saw erehT   esuoM .T dleiF yb
”.dluohs ti naem t’nseod detpmetta eb nac noitisop a esuaceb tsuJ“
.uoy ton tub ,haeY“ ”.erofeb skcos ni ecim nees ev’uoY“
.yllufhsab dias eh ”,wonk I ,seY“
”.liatbob a truh ot redraH
.meht rof rood eht denepo
.pu ti gniggof htaerb
.reveileb a saw eH
.derepsihw eilrahC ”,tnimreppep naht retteb neve s’tahT .hoO“
ygolohtna syadilwoH yppaH eht ni
”?’sffum‘ naem uoy t’noD“
.gnitiaw dna deraperp saw rennid suoiciled a erehw
,srehto dna ,yrots siht dnif nac uoY
.deffocs eH ”!uoy era oS“
.kniw etavirp a nosremE gnivig
.sesion gnirettihc tnerehocnI
.dehtuom ehs ”?reit kcosliaT“
dna slriwt emos did ehs
.ecaf reh no kool yrgnuh a ,deerga knuks eht ”,si eruS“
.emos gnibbarg ,ti denepo dna nit eikooc sih debbarg ylevislupmi ehS
”.tcejbus deidutsrednu yrev a s’tI ?yas nac ohW“
.ni gnitteg saw ria dloc nehw yllaicepse
”.thginot ykcul ’nitteg er’ew
”.elbigirrocni er’uoY“ .delims nosremE
.selas gnivigsknahT eht gnirud mih rof ti thguob d’ehS ”.puY“
”.ecnamor ot ’reit kcosliat‘ a s’erehT
.ebyam ,mM ?gnidraobwons ,woN“
.bmil artxe na ekil reh dnuora liat sih gnilruc ,ylthgil dessefnoc nosremE
”.enac ydnac a ekil kool I“
”.o-esuom ,pihsnoitaler ruo ni level wen a si sihT“
,knuks yffulf ,lager A
,elihwnaem ,nosremE
,reh tog I tahw sees
”?reh teg uoy did tahW ?yhW“
.detsisni eilrahC
otno levarg morf denrut eH
”?mmh ,neppah sgniht tel tsuj s’teL“
”?sreloraC“ .desaet ehs
.depirts saw ,stnemele eht morf sliat sselruf ,niht tcetorp ot dengised ,kcos lamreht ehT
”?ereh ew evah tahW“
.taorht sih deraelc nosremE
.tfig reh ta gnicnalg
”,citaborca yllarutan era slerriuqS
.derettum eilrahC ”,slleb hgielS“
”,erofeb tniaf lrig a edam reveN“ ”.tniaf
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht
”,’reit kcosliat‘ ni gnieb fo tceffe-edis deton a s’tahT“
.emit eht ta gninialpmoc t’nerew uoY“
.roiretxe erumed sih hguorht kaerb ot gniyrt
ehs retfA“ .walc a htiw ropav eht ni ecaf yelims a werd ehS
,s’02 reh ni saw ehS
”reiT kcosliaT“ saw sihT
.ecaf dereksihw reh tuoba gniwollib htaerb
.wot ni egakcap a
”.ssa yobmraf ,enif ruoy ta ,haeY“
.ti deen ot hguone dloc yllanif saw tI
.meht delahni ehs sa sreksihw reh ffo welf sbmurC
a fo rebmem driht eht osla saw ehS
.mih ta deknilb lerriuqs ehT ”?mM“ ” … stfig elbaraew ,hu ,fo gnikaepS“
.seikooc edamemoh fo nit a ot txen draobhsad eht no egakcap reh gnittup ,deralced ehs
.htuoy dna ygrene cinam reh ffo gniwohs ,spael
.sgnidit taerg gnignirB“
”.retrats-erif a m’I ,uoy rof ykcuL
,knuks onibla nA ”’.s’eineeuQ“‘
,relevart wollef ruoy
.robhgien sih sa llew sA
.delggig esuom ehT
,floWcaM boR yb daer
,dias eh ,deciton t’ndah eilrahC ecniS
detivni neeb dah yehT
.s’03 sih ni saw eh elihw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”!kcos ruoy fo dne eht nO“ ”?huH“
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT morf
.thgileldnac ot teS
.tfig reh aivodleS gnidnah ,dias eilrahC
.dneirflrig sih saw eilrahC
.weiv retteb otni egadneppa elisneherp ,ypor
”esuoM .T dleiF“ yb
.evoba tnemtrapa eht ni devil dna teertS niaM no renid a denwo ehS .aivodleS saw eman laer reh
lla s’tI“ ”?tbuod on ,ffo nekat eb ot dengiseD“
.s’eineeuQ“‘ ta eerios etavirp a ot
!etuc ylsuolucidiR“
.devirra d’eh wonk reh gnittel
”!doog era eseht ,kceH“
.esuap a saw erehT
?sllih eht tub ,gniht epipflah taht toN
.daor eht no kcab evord nosremE
”.erats annog s’enoyrevE“ .etihw dna deR
,wodniw ssalg dloc eht ot eson reh desserp eilrahC
”,ffo decils liat ym gnitteg dna gnillaf fo diarfa m’I
”.yllaer ,dluoc llits I ,naem I
”‘—ey ,sey‘ gnimaercs erew uoy ,llacer I fI
”,yoj retaerg ,yllufepoh ,dnA
.tnetnoc rettirc citnamor ni sezilaiceps ohw
”.kcab ruoy tuo worht d’uoy dias uoy dnA“ .delggig ehS
,detnap ehs ,rood eht gninepO
,tnetnoc rettirc citnamor ni sezilaiceps ohw
”.kcos deroloc-hself a naht retteb hcuM
,redic dellum fo ssalg a revo dereep eilrahC
!tiaw ,on ,hoo … ekiL
.esuap lufthguoht A ”.eoteltsiM
”.oot ,snettim-rae deen ll’uoY .mmH“
”!tirips evitsef eht ni
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,syadiloH yppaH
”!elbaroda’s ,hhaaA“ .skeehc reh no swap reh tup dna liat sih desaeler ehS ”.kcosliat a nI .uoY“ !kaeuqS
,ekaw reh ni stnirp-wap gnivael ,kcurt eht ot wons eht hguorht derepmacs ehS
.remmus eht revo tuokooc a ta tem d’yehT .ytreporp gniredrob a demraf
”.eineeuQ htiw taht yrt dluohs ew ebyaM“
”.enac ydnac hctocsrettub a ekil kool uoY !snevaeH“ .delggig ylneddus ehs ,nosremE ta gnikooL
?hguoht ,eb ti dluow suoicerp woH“
esuac ,hguoht ,gnitaks deeps toN“
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.stnedor owt eht htiw emoseerht gniremmis
.dehctiwt sreksihw siH
”.gnineppah ton s’taht ,haeY“ .seye eulb sih dellor nosremE
sih deleer eilrahC
”?srehto emos era tahW“ .dias eilrahC
”reiT kcosliaT“   ,yojne esaelP
,edis regnessap eht ot yaw reh no sthgildaeh eht dessorc ehs sA
.tniaf annog m’I !etuc oot s’ti ,yaw rehtiE ?sevolg-rae rO .snettiM“
,rood tnorf s’lerriuqs xof eht ta smaeb hgih s’pukcip sih dehsalf esuom tsevrah maerc-dna-dlog eht ,yawevird ywons reh otni dellup nosremE sA
”.nees ev’I .wonk I“
dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,tnemtrapa reh ot pu dna edisni meht derehsu ehS
”!mmM“ ”.sessalom regniG“
,ssenkrad rebmeceD eht otni rood tnorf eht tuo deppop eilrahC nehw nroh sih knoh ot tuoba saw nosremE
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.hctam eht thgil ot esle enoemos deen tsuj uoY“ ”.ton mA“
”?daerbregniG“ ”.sknahT“
”!seerged ythgie -derdnuh-eno nrut nac swap-toof ruO“
?spilf gniod ,spmar eht ffo gnioG
.nwot otni gnidaeh ,tnemevap