".emoh teg ew nehw uoy rof ekac llits s'ereht erus ekam lliw htuR"
".dneirflrig ruoy htiw secaf yssik gnikam eno taht tneps uoY"
.pu nug eht thguorb dna drawrof deppets eiknarF
.nam dlo eht morf erofeb tnemitnes fo sespmilg nees dah eH ".pup" ro "buc"
.drow rehtona tuohtiw nav eht fo tuo tog neht dna
.noitnetta yna ressarah sih evag eh erofeb yaw s'tehctaH ecnalg a detirem sihT ?wehpeN  .taps eh
gniyas s'eH :ikahK rof etoN( ".hsehsentir reN .tuo hstreg eno reN .rrrD" .ecaf gnimrofsnart sih hguorht detalucitra eh
?yhW"  ".gnihtyna rof
"?ew era ,niaga retnec gniniart redrO
.emoh kcab deppihs I nehw redrO eht rof boj a em tog nevE
tsisamerpus etihw a gniwohs
.deeps gnikcohs htiw rab tiperced eht ssorca daerps deedni did semalf dna
,rednetrab eht tub ,DI sih rof hcaer ot detrats ymmaS
,dnegel gnivil eht
.gniredloms ti teg ot hguone tsuj
".tseb od I tahw od ot ni em dellac dneirf ym
.dias eh ",sesmadA maS owT"
".mih ot netsil ot evah t'nod uoY"
.mra hcae no deoottat sessorc citlec dna
.ssecorp ot tol a dah ymmaS
.seégétorp fo niahc gnol a ni eno tsuJ
".redrum rof liaj ni su worht dna pu wohs spoc eht nehw esrow teg yletinifed ll'tI"
sihT"  sexeleB .Z .J yB
,sdnah koohs owt ehT ".lraC
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,sexeleB .Z .J yb ”!élO¡ gniraeT“
.teef sih otno tpael dna
.ylthgils delbmert ylno taht eciov a ni deksa
.ykcits dekool elbat loop eht nevE
".sknird rof tuo gniog er'ew os
,tius sih rednu morf tuo nug a dellup eH
.pmil tnew eh litnu mih dekohc dna
taorht eht yb mih debbarg ymmaS
,rettib eht fo pis a koot eH
",dik" naht rehto gnihtyna mih dellac dah tehctaH emit tsrif eht saw siht
.tceffe citamard evoba ton saw tehctaH neve tub
".seno roirefni eht tuo staeb seiceps retteb ehT
.ecaf sih ni ,rehtar ro
,elcnu na ro tnua na sa ot detaler yllautca t'nerew yeht etamkcap roines yna fo kniht ot degaruocne erew sbuc ,sey ,elihW
.nees reve ev'I sehctibmus tsehguot eht fo eno er'uoY .xineohP ,pu uoy nehguot ot em deen t'nod uoY"
,mih rof gnimoc ressarah lanigiro rieht ees ot pu dekool eH
.sregnif nezorf sih fo tuo nug eht gniyrp
.ybab a dna efiw a htiw yob A
tuhs htuom sih tpek ymmaS tuB
",ereh gnoleb t'nod uoY"  .dab ton tuB
".esle ydobyna naht ta retteb er'uoy gniht eno si ereht tuB
,trac erutinruf ytpme na htiw
yteixna laicos dna
"?dik ,wehpen ym htiw melborp a tog uoY"
"',lios dna doolB'"  "!TUO
.rettalc elbirroh a htiw revo ti gnilppot dna elbat a otno gnillaf
.tihsllub yrartibra era sdradnats ruoy tub ,enoyreve naht retteb er'uoy kniht sizaN uoY"
.on ...tuB .srehto eht ot gnilaed saw tehctaH tahw naht htaed renaelc a eb dluow tI
?ylimaf sa mih fo kniht yllaer tehctaH did tuB
"!nacixeM m'I taht erus neve ton er'eW
gnimoyW otni redrob eht dessorc tsuj dah yehT
.smaerd tsuj erew yeht spahrep ro ,smaerd sih ni seiromem doohdlihc fo seohce
.dehsinif neeb evah dluow eh ,daeh eht ot tohs a neeb dah ti fI .dooG .tohs tug A
digir tnew enobkcab s'ymmaS
kcen s'yob eht dnuora dnah rehto sih depparw eH
,ereh tuo )"tsaeB eht" sa nwonk(
elbat eht fo edis eht debbarg tehctaH
stekcop s'nam taf eht hguorht gnitoor detrats dna elttob eht deppord eH
"?su fo eno ...ton er'uoy tuB"
teef sih otno redaelgnir eht deluah ymmaS
.tuhs etuor taht gnilaes tlob evissam a fo gnidils eht neht
,edisflow yawflah
.teef gniladep-llits sih ffo mih detfil dna
,sespmilg tog eh semitemoS
,ysaerg a fo reens tnenamrep eht rednu flesmih dnuof ymmaS
,sknird rof tuo gniog er'ew uoy dlot I
?yltsenoH .diulf krad
.yrtnuoc siht ni nrob neeb dah eh
,stsif sih dehcnelc eH
.sdranni nwo sih fo roloc eht
",gnirepmihw on ,buc ,ekas s'dog roF"
,pu doots tius a ni nam redlo ,taf A
.gnol os koot I yhw em ksa t'nod srotagitsevni os won 119 llac retteb I ,yawynA"
.roolf eht ot derettalc nug ehT
sregnif sih morf degreme swalc prahs ,gnoL
,drawrof deppets neht dna
emos ot gniog yllaer ton er'eW
tsuj uoy od rO ?ssendam ruoy ot dohtem a ereht sI
.tehctaH dna mih redrum ot yrt ot gniog erew yehT .redruM
.srehto eht lla htiw enod saw eh ecno
.ti morf gninrael ton tsuJ
.kcap evitpoda sih ni ecalp sih dnif ot gniyrt morf
,gnihsilbuP pihstekcoR s'nogarD ehT morf
.s0491 eht ni detrats dah eh boj a eunitnoc ot ereh tuo emoc dah eH
"?tahW"  .delbmum ymmaS
elbat eno revo mih tseraen nem owt eht devohs eH
.tol eht fo dne raf eht ta dekrap yeht sa dias eh
.nam dlo eht ekil t'nsaw eh tub
.mih no noitnetta s'rotnem sih leef ot ymmaS rof nrut ot deen t'ndid tehctaH
,ti til dna htuom sih ni eno kcuts eH
si yrots s'yadoT dna
.taes sih otni kcab depmuls ymmaS
tsev mined a ni gniht ynwarcs a ,mih tseraen yob eht ot ti dednah dna
emoh yaw eht fo tser eht edor oud eht dna
.nwonk adluohs I" .deppans ymmaS
.ecaf sih naelc ot nug retaw s'rab eht desu dna
"?huh ,ledom tsetal eht er'uoy oS"
",enim fo dneirf a s'renwo raB"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
nav sih fo kcab eht denepo eh sa dias tehctaH
.rood eht ta klab mih neve edam ti nehw
.egnellahc a eb nac syug uoy rof krow cidem dleif tub
,snoitatcepxe s'tehctaH ot pu evil t'ndid eh fi tsael tA
.rehto hcae wenk yeht ekil detca nam rehtien tub
,tsap evord yeht ecno ,edis rehto ehT
,daeh s'nam eht dnuora meht depparw eh sa
.sizaN-oeN drawot ecneloiv dna
,kcab dehcrul tehctaH
.retnuoc eht tsniaga pot eht dehsams
"?sllab eht tog uoy kniht uoY
meht rof gnitiaw saw renwo eht erehw ,edistuo etsah lla edam owt ehT
,lamron ylgnibrutsid saw tsaeB eht edisni ria eht dna
!élO¡ gniraeT  yojne esaelP
dah eH .sraey sselemoh sih gnirud htlif fo ytnelp nees dah ymmaS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.emit siht enot sih otni gnipees ti pleh t'ndluoc ymmaS tub
:nommoc ni sgniht lareves dah rab siht ni snamuh enin lla deciton
.kcen s'yob eht gnippans deredisnoc eh
.daeh devahs a dna
...teef sih otno flesmih deluah dna
.sknird rof ereh tuo yaw eht lla emoc t'ndah
,tem reve evah I rekcufrehtom yrenro tsom ,tsehguot eht eb yam tehctaH eht ttekcaH"  "?em esucS'" .dellac saw eh tahw ta daeh sih detlit tub ,ti koohs ymmaS
.daor eht morf seye sih detrevid reven tehctaH ,evord eh nehW
retnuoc eht dniheb deklaw ylmlac eH
,demaercs ymmaS "!TEHCTAH"
pu ekops tehctaH ",raeh
".retteb eb ot uoy tcepxe I
.skcotsnekriB fo riap hserf a otni
.rethguals eht ot ytrap eb ot tub eciohc on dah ymmaS ,tniop siht tA  )".sessentiw oN
".duorp em ekam ,knarF"
eugnot sih dnuof yllanif ymmaS
.lihP ro uoy sa nuf hcum sa ton s'eno sihT"
.hctiws dna tiab t'nod I wonk uoy ,diK"
teef dalc-kcos sih deppils eh sa
,did tehctaH mih ot tog dnA
,sretspmud fo tuo netae
.siht rof em deen t'ndid uoY
.ecneloiv ni dexamilc t'ndah thgin eht fi sa
htaerb sih hctac ot tnemom a koot flowerew eht ,doolb dna arecsiv htiw deniats sehtolc derettat htiW
.mrots a epacse ot moorhtab cilbup a fo roolf eht no tpels neve dah emit eno dna
,niaga daor eht no erew yeht neht dnA
dna lohocla fo elttob a pu dekcip eH ".sessentiw
elbat eht no selttob ytsud fo riap a decalp
tehctaH  ".ylno setihW .rab ruo si sihT"
?ti gniriuqca fo krow eht lla ot og yhw ,etsat deriuqca na saw gnihtemos fI
.sehtolc fo tes naelc a tuo dellup dna
'tiaB' .tiab t'nerew uoy dnA .stsicar eseht rof hguone krad er'uoY"
.rorroh tcejba htiw decalper reens eht
.deggurhs lraC  .deksa eh
naidnI saw lios siht rof tneps doolb ehT
snamuh yb no detnemirepxe gnieb morf DSTP htiw flowerew denahpro na tuoba si hcihw
ydob sih fo tuo llaf ot tellub eht rof emit ni tsuj
.meht dniheb eciov ysaerg a emac
.daor trid a sa debircsed eb ylsuoreneg ylno dluoc taht
,mih htiw emit dneps ot tnaw yltsenoh ot
,niaga stsif sih dellab ymmaS
...levon a ni dehsilbup meht steg eh litnu tsael ta
,neek sa ton saw gniraeh edisnamuh s'ymmaS hguoht nevE
,oS .ereht yttaf fo wal-ni-rehtorb eht s'feihc rieht esuaceb ,ti tuoba gnihtyna od t'ndluow spoC
".tfel shtaerb ynam evah t'nod uoy ,tsaf klaT
.moor eht fo retnec eht ot gnidael liart a deruop neht
,tehctaH ssentiw ot emit ni tsuj dnuora denrut eH
.yrotsih gniyduts neeb evah syob uoy ekil smeeS '.lioS .dnA .doolB'"
.pu mih nam" ot tsuj ylno fi
.mih hctaw ot dnuora deppihw sdaeh rehto eht lla dna
.buc ,rehtie em eb ot uoy tnaw t'nod I"
.mih ot tog tehctaH nehw suoicsnoc eb t'ndluow eh tsael tA
".evah sruoy naht regnol raf ereh neeb evah srotsecna s'yob ym oS
.swalc sih edih ot ton tub
"?enoyna naht retteb er'yeht snigriv yrgna fo hcnub a gnihcaet ffo teg uoy'd erehW"
.daeh sih fo pot eht ot etargim ot detnaw hcihw srae
sllaw eht no emirg eht tuoba gnihtemos dias hcihW
ngis egral a ,llew ,saw
.slewot repap fo daw a htiw nwod ecaf sih dettap eh retfa dias tehctaH
.tuo ti taps dna
",rab sih nwod denrub tsuj uoY ?devlos melborP"
.ti detaicerppa reven ymmaS
daer ot elbaliava seires eht fo tser eht sah sexeleB .Z .J .nozamA no elbaliava dna
.ecnelis ercassam-tsop mirg eht gnicreip ylerab eciov teiuq sih ,desucca ymmaS
.seiceps sih fo erus ekam ot sropav cilohocla eht tsap gnihsup ,ffins rehtona lraC evag ymmaS
.dekrab nam taf eht ",rotiart ecaR"
.meht fo tuo llaf naht secarg doog s'tehctaH ni peek ot aedi retteb a ylbaborp saw ti
annaw t'nseod dik siht hcihw seirotS"
,etteragic eht deppord tehctaH
.dneirf lautum ruo noitnem dna emoh s'nhoJ .tS pillihP rotaneS yb pord
".sizaN llik uoy 'nihctaw fo daetsni ,ekac erom gnitae emoh kcab eb dluoc I"  "?hO"
.terces a peek nac I tuB
".em ot yadhtrib 'nikcirf yppaH
,detanimulli ecafrus sti fo sdriht-owt ylno htiw
".emit fo etsaw a saw erus taht
.tsaeB eht tsniaga gninael
tehctaH  .tius sih rednu delaecnoc ,oot soottat emos dah redael rieht ylbamuserP
.sessentiw oN .uoy dlot I"
.srettel eulb gib ni
,manteiV ni thguof evah ot hguone dlo dekool ohw nam dlab yltrop a
.nam taf eht fo pot no dednal dna
.elddadeks retteb owt uoY
?em hcaet ot 'niyrt uoy era tahW
.delkcuhc lraC  .dias ymmaS
kcits suoixon eht gniffup
.dias ecaf ymrams eht ",rettam t'nseoD"
.tcaer dluoc eh erofeb
".nur ot ydaer teG"
.ti dneps ot detnaw eh woh ton saw gniniart tabmoc dna
rood tnorf eht sdrawot detlob neht ,rehtona otni dna
.edisnamuh ot denruter eh erofeb
,ytinamuH s'flowereW sa nwonk seires regral a fo trap deniatnoc-fles a ,sexeleB .Z .J yB !élO¡ gniraeT
eht fo ecar dirbyh a era snacixeM wonk d'uoy ,koob yrotsih a daer ot derehtob syob uoy fi ,wonk'Y"
.ezag latnem s'nam dlo ni tfihs eht leef dluoc ymmaS tuB
,epacse sih edam renwo eht sa rood kcab eht fo mals tnatsid eht raeh ot hguone prahs llits saw ti
.taorht s'ymmaS otni pu deliob sdroW
elttob eht fo stnetnoc eht dehsalps eH
,rehtona ro dnik emos fo soottat htiw pu dekram dna
tehctaH fo sedis htob no loots rehtiE
,delworg tehctaH
.uoy naht retteb era yllaer ohw elpoep eht ffo gnissip ta tseb er'uoY" .ni meht gniggid
,dias tehctaH ",ton ebyam ,ebyaM"
.sehsid eht gnihsaw ot denruter dna
".niaga uoy gniees doog saw ti ...treboR
",diputs 'nieb tsuj ,gnihtoN"
.edis s'etamkcap sih ot gnihsur
?nam dlo ,taht s'tahW ?haeY"
,tnega na gnieb sa gniticxe sa gnihtoN
.seman 'stnerap sih llacer neve t'ndluoc llits eH
.draobhsad eht tsniaga tsif sih demmals ymmaS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.mih ta detcerid saw eciov eht dezilaer eh nehw
"?yadhtrib rieht rof rab a ot enoemos ekat ot raey lanoitidart eht 12 t'nsI .desufnoc m'I"
.dnah sih dednetxe dna
elibomredrum tneicna sih gnivird sag no tneps tehctaH yenom eht htiw
".tehctaH ,eb ot tnaw t'nod I
.amoc a otni yob nacixeM a taeb sdik eseht ,oga sthgin elpuoC"
.dias ymmaS ",esaelP"
.srab nar ohw seiddub dlo fo dne on evah ot demees tehctaH
"?siht si tahw ,won yeH"
".tuoyap ecnarusni na teg ll'I ,yaw siht tsael tA
teg oS .lios ruo ,doolb ruO
.teef rieht ot depmuj sdaehniks eht fo eno elgnis yrevE .ti did taht ,hO
dias evah dluoc ymmaS ,esruoc fO
,ton ro reeb eerF
".rettam taht rof ,vaG neve rO
.dias tehctaH ",t'ndid uoy tuB"
tuo dehcaer eh ,detaminaeR
?tehctaH ,tuoba lla siht s'tahW"
,eciov gnilgrug ,teiuq a nI
",sevoD norI" levon ygolohtna ytirahc eht ni dehsilbup eb ot nesohc saw ",srovaF"
,ymmaS ot resolc deppets renwo rab ehT
.ffo ymmaS devohs dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.ereh ni emac eporuE fo tser eht erofeb gnol aciremA lartneC dezinoloc ohw hsinapS eht dna snaciremA evitaN
.taht ot dnopser ot woh aedi on dah eH
.sllaw sti edisni dekoms etteragic yreve fo tsohg eht yb detnuah neeb evah tsum rab ehT
.gnihcaorppa enoemos draeh eh revenehw pu gnikool ylno
,spotretnuoc eht no nerhterb sti tsniaga
htrae eht ni evoorg elbitpecrepmi-hgin a otni denrut dna
,derettum tehctaH ",élO"
.kcab delbmuts ressarah rieht taht tsaf os pu doots yllanif tehctaH
,nosaer eht revetahw ,lleW
,pu sdik esoht 'niraet uoy was I nehW
.ni dellif ylluf reven dah yromem s'ymmaS ni spag ehT ?ocixeM
.derif tnassip elttil ehT
.knarF otni nwod gnirob seye
.tniop eht ton s'tahT"
.ria eht ni nug eht desiar eh "...woN
daehniks dehsinotsa eht fo tnorf ni saw tehctaH
,gniht nam dlo nrobbuts a rehtie saw siht demussa dna
.hself fo gniraet eht dna smaercs eht raeh dluoc eh ,mih dniheB
...ekil tsomla saw ti
,owt eht neewteb ecaps eht dehctaw ymmaS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.maN' ni kcab tnuoc nac I naht semit erom efil ym devas ohw nam a rof yllaicepsE
.nwo ruo dnal siht edam ohw seno eht era setihW"
...srae sih ni gnidnuop saw traeh s'ymmaS ,tniop siht tA
,sevlowerew regnuoy tsom fo tuo suzeejeb eht deracs )b dna ,knurd teg t'ndluoc )a ohw nam a roF
,yadhtrib sih ,lla retfa ,saw tI
.tuo steg eno oN .rooD"
nihc laminim htiw ecaf tuo-nward
".gnoleb uoy erehw ocixeM ot kcab oG"
.rorroh ni gnimaercs ,seenk sih ot llef eH
.ti fo ekam ot tahw neve rO
.tneiciffE .krow dooG"
?siht gniod erew yeht yhw taht saW
loots a no flesmih detnalp tehctaH
.tehctaH ,ereht kcab ti tsol tsomla I ...I
.lraC ,erusaelp a syawlA"
,trAtnaiveD dna dapttaW ,ytiniffAruF no
.ria eht ni sregnif fo riap a desiar dna
"?ti t'nsaw ,gnola lla nalp eht saw sihT"
.gniksa er'uoy tahw s'taht fi ,flowerew a toN"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
".syadhtrib esrow dah ev'uoY .buc ,no emoc hO"
?tnassip elttil uoy ,gniod er'uoy kniht uoy'd tahW"
.ytiC radeC ni kcab srab eht fo eno ot og ot tsuj repaehc neeb evah dluow ti
.ni evird eht no ereht ni neeb t'ndah taht gek latem a deciton ymmaS
.rehtie ,doog toN .dah taht toN
",neht ,esucxe na saw I oS"
,nwod ezag sih tpek dna deredduhs eH
,.C.D ni reve er'uoy fI
yawhgih eht ffo dereev tehctaH nehw
.senur dna stonk citleC dna semalf dna slluks fo yrellag a
.ssenisub ym fo tfel saw tahw yawa evord dna pu denrut selohssa esoht erofeb saw ti sa tiforp a gnikam ylerab saw I ,diK"
.nam taf eht ta nihc sih dettuj tehctaH
?yadhtrib dr32 sih etarbelec ot ymmaS detnaw tehctaH woh saw sihT
,sruls laicar sedulcni yrots s’yadoT - gninraw tnetnoC
.s'tehctaH fo yddub dlo rehtona ot tuo nrut dluow rab eht fo renwo eht ro
.desserpminu yletelpmoc ,esruoc fo ,saw
,sdaeh devahs ,etihw
,odavarb fo yalpsid hsiloof ylevisserpmi na ni ,retoohs siH
sdrawnwod enO  ".uoy naht tfel shtaerb erom evah I ...dnA
.taht tuoba retteb tlef eh ,wohemos dnA
.reeb emos rof tsuj evird gnol a si
ydaer eb ot uoy tnaw I
tehctaH nehw depmuj syob eht fo lareveS
,tnemom krad ,trohs a ,tnemom a roF
.reeb fo laeppa eht ees yllaer t'ndid eh ,dlot eb hturT
ymmaS taht neht saw tI
...on ho ...tnaem hcihW
,tehctaH fo tuo lleh eht detcepser ymmaS
",lraC ,devlos melborP"
,pac eht ffo detsiwt evah ylisae sa tsuj dluoc eH
.laiceps os t'nsaw eh wenk eh won ,gniht eno roF
.ymmaS naht retsaf taes sih ni dnuora deleviws tehctaH
.niaga ecno ta syug ruof thgif ot doom eht ni ton m'I"
.thgis a railimaf oot lla saw ti dnA
demees etamkcap redle sih ,neht tuB
.saw eh ohw t'nsaw taht ,oN
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.noitceles larutan
.nemodba sih fo tuo dehsug doolB
,gninihw detah tehctaH wenk eH ".niaga
niatrec ytterp saw eh tub ,egatireh nacixeM emos evah llew yrev dluoc eH
"?tihsllub taht htiw sdaeh ruoy gnillif s'ohW"
".efil ruoy ot taerht lautca na seilpmi
,seires siht ni yrots rehtonA
.niaga mrahPoiB ekil
?tiab saw I ,oS"
.mih no saw noitnetta siH
.egar gniworg s'ressarah eht yb desserpminu ,detaeper tehctaH
.tnuoc ot sesseccus rehto sih evah dluow nam eht
.etah htiw detpurroc dah eh sdnim esohw syob eht htiw eid ot eelem eht otni mih dessot dna
.sdrawot gnikrow s'eh hcihw
s'tI"  ".nwo ruoy toN .doolb kcalb dna
.ytip fo tuo eb ot dah ti erehw tniop eht dessap oga gnol dah yehT ".pu
",élO gniraeT"  ".oH retaW"
!gnip elbidua na htiw roolf eht ot llaf dna
".ti tsol ti tsol tsomla I
.t'ndluoc eh ,on ,llew
.spit regnif sih rednu deirub yats ot swalc sih gnilliw
doolb pu daw a pu dehguoc
.ésalb ylrettu saw tehctaH
htiw elzzup eht fo seceip rehto eht dedivorp
llew haeY" .delbmurg ymmaS
.ecaf on dah ylneddus knarF dna ,epiws
.daeh sih dellor dna sredluohs sih depmuls ymmaS
saw sihT   .ecnelis ni
dnim ni noitanitsed etinifed a dah eh taht ngis ylno ehT
,redluohs eht no mih dettap dna edis s'knarF ot revo dehcrul nam taf ehT
".llet dluoc eh seirots eht ,hO
,did eh nehw tuB .netfo ekoj a dekcarc ohw nam a ton saw tehctaH .delworg ymmaS
.me' fo tuo nem gnikam dna sdik deracs gnikat fo ybboh a sah nam eht tub
"elo gniret" gniyalpsid
"?skcikedis 'nivah ekil
.guh raeb thgit a rof ni yddub dlo sih dellup tehctaH neht
...dnah ta melborp eht ot kcaB
.mih rof thguob-ton dah tehctaH knird eht deffins dna thgir s'redle sih ot eno eht otno flesmih derewol eh os ,sunatet tcilfni ot ylekil sa tsuj demees
.rethgil a dna setteragic fo kcap a dnuof eh litnu
...tub ",uoy knaht ,oN"
?uoy ekil tsuj eb nac I oS
.seot ruoy no yats ot deen uoy tuB
.tehctaH ta reens sih demia eH
".uoy ta dam llits m'I"
"?kcabtew eht od ot stnaw ohW"