.sregnif sih ni tnemtsujda eht gninrut elihw
”?neppah taht did woH“
ehT .htiw od ot tahw wenk enoyna naht setalp eht dnuora skrof dna snoops erom dna
.dik eht ot gnicnalab daol nialpxe ot yrt naht
”.nwod yaw ruo krow dna pot retnec eht htiw
,hcaer s’mra nihtiw doots ssertiaw ehT
tahW“ .dnuora dekool dna
.ecin yrev saw ehs ,oN“
”?rolias ,knurd uoy
.emit siht reduol tuo llac estuN
eW .emit gnitsaw pots os ,melborp lacirtcele na ylraelc si
.ylhsipeehs dennirg ztloB
.debmilc dna esacriats rehtona yb desuap ohw estuN htiw pu hctac ot deirruh dna ylkciuq dewob ztloB  ”.su
.dezzub dnah estuN ni retem ehT
,pihs eht
.ssertiaw eht rof erom deirrow eH
dna snotsip dettif ylroop fo gnilbmur eht revo sdrow s’rentrap sih tuo ekam ylerab dluoc ztloB
”.pirt eht fo tser eht rof diap ton era uoy ees ll’I .derif er’uoY“
tnemtsujda eht ekam ot reisae saw tI
”?ereh ni ew erew nehw
s’ikiK ”.steser dleif eht nehw dleihs tnemniatnoc eht edistuo eb ot tnasaelpnu si
.nroh eht morf detpure sgniw egral fo gnitaeb eht ekil dnuos wol A
erehT .niatpac eht fo egami eht deziniturcs eH
elihw elbat a ta mih taes ot retiaw eht dewolla ztloB  ”.em wolloF“
hcum knumpihc A .lesuorac eht rof enil eht fo tnorf eht ot stnerap gnilworg
.enihcam emit eht fo pot eht ot noitcerid estuN dewollof ztloB
.gnilbmert sredluohs reh
”.emit ruoy gnitsaw er’uoY“
ti ssorca depiws eH
.rotatceps esirnus eht
evah ll’I .setunim evif tog ev’ew ,lleW“ .deggurhs estuN
.ediug eht dnuora dna latrop eht hguorht degrus dworc ehT ".em
tI .emit no kcab teg ot
t’nsI“ .enigne eht fo semuf eht llems dna
yrots s’yadoT dna
.edis eht ot dehcrul pihs ehT
teef reh ot reh dellup revaeb ehT
.ylrae tuo meht tips ylneddus edir eht fi dellik neeb dah yeht demussa tsom
.norpa etihw a gniraew
eH ”.edis rehto eht morf ti ta kool ot deen
.ediug ruot ruoy ,ikiK
delims ehS .nroh eht morf wolleb a yb tuo denword saw drow tsrif reh tub ,htuom reh denepo ikiK
.sraluconib hguorht noziroh eht dennacs elgae nA
.roolf eht dednuop liat sih sa dnuos gnippals a saw erehT
.moor eht dnuora cra na ni retem eht detniop estuN
dooG“ .srood elbuod egral erofeb doots mrofinu etihw lamrof a ni revaeb a erehw
.sreliob gnissih eht morf deruop retaW
yM“ .tsehc reh ot dewob saw daeh reh dna ,koohs sredluohs ’ssertiaw ehT
.ti fo tnorf ni gnidnats elom
yrenihcam elbidercni eht erimda ot tnemom a
.llaw eht no sleehw denrut srehto ehT ".srood
,maerd a t’nsaw tI .gniyrc elpoep
llA .orez dehcaer latrop eht revo retnuoc ehT
ev’I“ .daeh sih dehctarcs
.selballys detcennocsid wef a tub tuo ekam ylerab dluoc
ll’I .tnemecalper a redro ot
.sriats eht ot nar eh sa mih rednu morf tuo gel ’ztloB kconk ot denetaerht retaw gnihsuR
.recuas eht ni puc sih
A ”.eson sih gnuts lio gninrub eht dna
ehS ”.elpoep eht htiw gnitcaretni
.sdnah sih ni repap fo dap a dna licnep a htiw
.loop gnimmiws eht evah ew ereh dnA“
nO .edurc os erew sgnittif dna sgnihsub ehT
.mussopo eht fo smra eht ni yawa gnillorts lerriuqs eht ta detniop ztloB
reh ,nwod yaw reh dekcip dna
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
dna semit erom nezod a noitom eht detaeper eH
,elbissop tsap eht fo elpoep htiw tcaretni ekam ot tsixe ot dah noitairav fo tnuoma llams A
cra ediw a ni enac reh gnigniws ikiK fo mrof enol eht rof detrap srood ehT
.gnitsohg fo ecart on saw
,emit eht dekcehc eh
”.evif evif orez xis eno thgie neves evif ruof dias I“
”.noitcelfer a esuac ro langis a htiw erefretni dluow taht gnihtemos rof kooL
.roolf eht tih ti erofeb eutats eht thguac dna devid revaeb ehT ”.em nodraP“
.melborp eht gnisuac werc eht htiw gnitcaretni era stseug eht fo emos ebyaM“
llaw eht gnola yaw reh deppat ehS
,yaler tsrif eht morf kcilc tniaf a saw
”.dlrow eht ni emit eht lla evah eW
”,mrofinu fo tuo er’uoY“
”?gnineppah si tahW
.egde eht morf reh detrocse dna lerriuqs gniylf eht ot
”.gniknis dna grebeci na gnittih fo regnad ni si pihs siht ,setunim ytnewt ni ,riS“
.em wollof lliw uoy fi
”.dleif eht htiw gnissem yllaer si gnihtemoS
.ti tuoba od nac uoy gnihton si erehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
?sris ,edur neeb ehs saH“
.retaw eht otni reh depleh dna smra sih ni ssertiaw eht dleh eH
a ,latrop dnuor eht fo edis eno revO
nI .dnaL levarT emiT ot
.erofeb eveihca ot elba neeb reven dah ti taht ecnelis dna deeps a htiw devom enigne eht dna deppord esion ehT
eH .emit ni ti retne dna ,nruter
denethgiarts ssertiaw ehT
”.dexif eb ot sdeen tahw wonk ot dnamed I .niatpac eht m’I“
.moor eht decap eh dna pots-
dah emitaeT .arbalednac eht otni dezag dna soihcatsip sih dewehc ztloB natiT ,reenigne daeH  .derettups eh
sraey evif eht ni melborp tsethgils eht dah ton
,gnorts smees htgnerts dleiF“
taht sllaw dna srood eht fo ecnelupo dna retsul a dedda thgil mraw eht tub
ll’eW .ytrid eb thgim kcol esahp tibuq eht ekil skool ti tub ,edis siht no melborp on si
.ti was eh erus t’nsaw ztloB kciuq os deneppah
”.llaf ot tuoba saw ehS“
ro gnicnad erew yeht elihw grebeci eht tih pihs eht dna
.eutats a gnilppot
.hguone duol t’nsaw llits ti tub
.delknirw eson sih dna V a demrof sworbeye siH
dna enihcam emit eht fo pot eht tsniaga nwod emac ti sa tneb rab nori yvaeh ehT .revo ti
?og yeht did
eH ”.emit txen ereh trats dna niaga yrt ot evah ll’eW .emit fo tuo
dna ,degnis erew sagot
yaP .esle enoemos rof uoy nekatsim sah ehS ?ti fo tahW“
.tnemssarrabme ni deltsirb liat reH
ztloB .ztloB ot esnes on edam taht shparg dna srebmun deyalpsid neercs ehT
sihT .moor enigne eht ot gniog er’eW“
.neht yb dehsinif eb dluohs yeht tuB
.ssertiaw eht ta deralg eH ”.ris ,yas uoy sA“
.edir taht no tnemngila laropmet eht kcehc ot eton latnem a edam ztloB   ”.lla
s’teL“ .nikpan eht htiw htuom sih depiw dna puc sih dehsinif
.yzarc gniog si retem ehT
”.gnitsohg eht ecudorper dluoc I ,noisiced rehto emos ekam meht edam I fi thguoht I
.htuom sih ni revirdwercs eht fo pit eht tup eh
.rethgual htiw deraor
”.etunim a rof tser dna ereh yatS .efas era yehT“
.llah eht nwod gnireev erofeb dnuora retem eht devaw estuN
erehT .tsacnwod a saw ztloB
.reh ot tnemom emas eht lla si tI“
.sreh morf dnah ztloB dellup dna elbat eht dnuora dehsur estuN ”.oN
.regnorts gnitteg era snoitallicso ehT“
.pu peek ot delggurts ssertiaw ehT
.stressed eht dennacs ztloB
erehT .retaw gnihsur fo dnuos eht yb dewollof moor eht hguorht detarebrever latem gnikaerc fo dnuos ehT ".esolc
?gniog ew era erehW“
.liardnah eht dehctulc dna dehceercs ssertiaw ehT
”,elbissopmi
dniheB .srotaderp egral fo etirovaf eht saw yorT ni rorreT
”.ssim ,ereht morf yawa emoc esaelP“
.senihcam ciahcra gnirotinom seiceps suoirav erehw moor llams a fo retnec eht ni doots mrofinu eulb krad a ni raeb a erehw moor lortnoc a ot pu dna
yawa edorts estuN   ”.yrt ot evah I“
.gnitpmet os dekool lla tI
.snoil deganeet gnihgual eerht fo sgel eht neewteb degdod eH
,arbalednac a ,htolcelbat ecal a htiw elbat a ta tas yehT
”cinatiT eht no emitaeT“ si
”?tuoba taht saw
si ehS“ .kool syawedis a mih evag estuN
A .enihcam emit eht ot retaw gnihsur eht tsniaga yaw rieht thguof yehT
,gninword neve ebyam
?reh rof sselepoh si saW
".pots lluf senignE .trop ot draH .daeha grebecI"   ,deralb nroh eht morf seciov eht dna desuap
,seenk reh ot llef ssertiaw ehT
.tsetorp ni demaercs lateM
s’tahT“ .kcab reh ta derats eh sa nepo gnuh htuom ’estuN ,reh dniheB
sa slortnoc eht
A .derekcilf egami
”.thgif ot tog reven I
teL“    .revirdwercs a htiw
dna nerdlihc gniyrc fo dworc eht hguorht yaw sih thguof ztloB natiT  hcinniM dieR yb
llorts dna ,ecnad ,tae
.ykcinif erew sedir levart emiT
.ton ro llaf ot gniog
.ezis dna ytuaeb ni rof pu edam ti ,ygolonhcet ni dekcal ti
.flesruoy fo elcatceps a ekam t’noD“  ”.gnihton did I“
dna ,meht drawot decar retaw fo llaw
.dleif eht ni noitallicso na s’ereht tub ,enif era scinortcele ehT
er’eW“ .ffo retem gnizzub eht ffo denrut dna elbat eht ot denruter estuN
”?rebmun eht saw tahW
ztloB ”.niaga enog s’tI ?tahW“
,sniugnep owt erew ereht ,tnatsni na roF
”.emit lla fo pihs esiurc yruxul tsetaerg eht ecneirepxe emoC“
.hteet sih hguorht detarg tub
tes eH ”.sgnidaer emos ekat s'teL“ .deggurhs estuN
”?lufituaeb ti
.sgel s’niatpac eht neewteb deklaw dna retem eht detekcop eH ”.ereh gnihtoN“
ztloB erofeb stun fo gab a decalp dna elbat eht ot pu delddaw niugnep A
.ereh enil ni erew sepyt lla fo serutaerC
s’tI .t'nac ew ,sah eno on ecnis tub
.ssertiaw eht ot denrut eH
woN .elbaknisnu si pihs siht swonk enoyrevE“
oT  .egral yltsom erew snortap eht dnaL levarT emiT ni ereh tub
erehT .nottub trats eht dehsup dna meht neewteb deppets ztloB
.swercs eht hguorht delbmum
eh ,pael lanif a htiw
enO .latrop eht no gnidnecsed ,noitcerid yreve morf gnimoc saw tseug krap gnilims fo maerts ydaets A
.pu mlap dnah a desiar eh dna daeh sih dekcoc
deirruh estuN .ecap sih dewols dna teef reh ot reh depleh ztloB
,dewolleb eciov s’niatpac ehT
latrop eht fo edis eno ot mroftalp a no gnidnats elom ehT
desolc eH ”.noitcnuflam a eb ot ralugerri oot s’tI
”.evom taht sthgil sah tI
.pots ot esion eht rof dnoces a detiaw dna
teef sih rednu devom edir ehT
owt dellup eH ”.noitpecxe na ekam dluoc ew ,ruoh siht
”.hguone dah ev’I woN .erofeb uoy denraw ev’I“
.edis eno no gnittis ylimaf oppih eht dettops dna
.moor eht dennacs estuN
desolc egami eht depiws ztloB ”.yaw ym nO“
”.ztlaw eht dna tortxof eht era emit eht fo secnad ralupop ehT
.strap dna tnempiuqe hcet-hgih fo tikloot a otni ecived eht deppord
,deralb edir tsrif eht fo ecnartne depahs-eltsac eht ni srekaeps ehT
ynA“ .dnats emorhc a ot ti dekooh
”.esneffo on tnaem I
.tahW“  ”.su htiw emoC“
.htaerb reh hctac ot gniyrt revo delbuod saw ohw ssertiaw eht deidaets ztloB
snezoD .thgirb dna yrd saw
.elbaknihtnu eht did eh ecnis
.yawrood a ot gnihcram dna leeh sih no denrut eH
.tlebloot sih morf revirdwercs eht gnillup
”.girb eht ni yad eht dneps ro egdirb eht ffo teg
.noitnetta rof roolf elbram eht no liat ediw sih deppals dna estuN fo tnorf ni dehsur eH
”.esuac eht si moor siht ni gnihtemoS“
.srood niam eht drawot dna revaeb eht dnuora deppets eH
.rednow ni derats raeb ehT
,enola saw ehs nooS
revirdwercs eht htiw rotautca eht detrohs eh
.noitnetta sih dleh elbat eht gnihcaorppa ssertiaw ylevol eht tub
.yawrood eht fo tuo dekop ecaf s’revaeb ehT  ”.og
edir eht no gnitiaw nerdlihc eht ta dekool
.ebut elbixelf a ot detcennoc nroh ralucric a otni delley dribgnikcom a
gnitsujda deen lliw recnalab daol eht tub ,nac I tseb eht nethgiarts
mih ta nwod derats xof rehtom a
ehT .eucser reh ot gninnur deredisnoc eh sa delbmert sgel siH
ev’eW .elacs eht ffO .aohW“ .elbat eht no gnitser ti ta nwod dekool eH
.gnilialf smra htiw gnola tpews saw nogard A
,rebmun tigid-enin a rebmemer
.srood aes eht esolC"
,yretsym a saw gniniatretne siht dnuof enoyna woH
”.flah ni em tuc eh erofeb stih wef a ni tog I
.slamina gninnur no gnillaf hsa gninrub dewohs ecnartne eht revo ngis
smra reh tuo dehcterts lerriuqs gniylf A
.esolc t'now rood aes
.tleb loot eht ot detniop revaeb ehT
.roolf eht gnola enac reh gnippat
.smra sih dessorc estuN ”.elbissopmI“
gniyrrac estuN drawot sriats eht nwod decar odexut a ni niugnep A
.htuom sih ni meht thguac dna etalp rettimsnart rosnet eht fo swercs eht deppop
,evah dluow enoemos neht ,dluoc
.dne tneloiv eht ot elttab eht fo trats mlac ylevitaler eht morf tfird ot dednet tI
.dezzub dnabtsirw sih
ekahs ot lenap ssecca eht gnivael ,gnitarg roolf eht hguorht llaf swercs eht fo tsal eht tel dna revirdwercs sih deppord ztloB  .dewolleb nroh eht ”,tih ev'eW"
”.ekips rehtona rof ereh tiaw ot evah ot gniog er’eW .deppots
t’nod I“ ,delbmurg eno driht ehT
hsilgnE s’neeuQ ni kaeps ot devol ohw gniwollof detacided a dah edir sihT
,moor enigne eht otni sriats larips eht dednuor eh sA
tneb dna annetna eht no thguac tI
.ruflus fo dekeer yeht
.eciov ylevol a dah dna
.ria eht otni deppop lenap ssecca eht fo swercs eht
”,ni neppah ot gniog si tahw gniwonk won thgir deifirret eb d’ehs ,esiwrehtO
”.knis dna grebeci na tih ot tuoba si pihs
tnemevoM .pu dekool ztloB  .detniop dna riats a no doots ssertiaw ehT ”.tuo kooL“
degrem yehT .ecarg decitcarp htiw mih dnuora degdod rehto eht
.sris doog ,nodrap ruoY“
”.gnitsohg tuoba gninialpmoc era
.syawedis llef eh erofeb spets wef a koot
”.krow t’now tI .t’nac uoY“
.etalume dluoc ega nredom eht ni eno on
,retaw dloc-eci eht ecneirepxe dna
.launam eht ni ton s’tI“
s’ikiK  .deraeppasid dna xob eht fo edis eht dehcuot yeht ,eno yb
reliart rotcart a fo ezis eht xob gnol a saw edir hcae
a sa ecnelis neddus saw
.sdnah htob htiw elbat eht debbarg eh ,dethgir ti nehW
ehT" .smra rieht gnivaw latrop eht tsap nar snogard ,reh dniheB
”.moor gninid niam eht rof deriuqer si eit kcaB .sris
elbat rieht ediseb emac elconom a htiw niugnep A
.pu dellac eh ”?tahW“
edir eht fo retnec eht ot derepmacs eH   ”.sdnoces ytnewT“
.evas tih dna srebmun eht ni deyek ztloB
.spsag deggar saw gnihtaerb
”?setunim enin ni neppah ot gniog si tahW
esle gnihtemoS .tlebloot sih morf retem htgnerts dleif a koot dna rennacs eht
”?tsap eht ni kcuts teg ew
”cinatiT eht no emitaeT“   :yojne esaelP
.roolf eht ssorca dehsaw retaw aes sa ezorf ehs tub
.deniarts saw gnihtaerb reH
.pihs eht fo wob eht ot langis eht dewollof estuN ”.yaw sihT
.woW“ .retem eht no ecaf sih htiw mih yb deklaw estuN
.enihcam emit eht fo reddal eht dednecsed eh sa daeh sih koohs estuN
.retem eht fo ecaf eht denaelc dna aet fo pis rehtona koot eH ”.setunim enin“
.serutcip fo egalloc lufetsat a saw emitaeT rof ecnartne ehT
.ecanruf a otni laoc delevohs snogard ,ecnatsid eht nI
".pots lluf senignE
.skeehc sih fo edis eno ot meht dehsup dna htuom sih ni meht thguac eH
ta“ ,ylwols daeh sih koohs revaeb eht ”,lleW“   ”?esaelp owT .gnol eb t’now eW .ytrap emutsoc etavirp a rof desserd er’eW“
,su rebmemer uoy fI“
,mih deifirroh snaem lufetsaw a hcus yb thgil gnicudorp fo tpecnoc ehT
.daeh sih denrut ztloB .yb tpews teg
.elddup eht dnuora deppets ehs dna
,estuN htiw dedilloc eno
.latrop eht otni meht werht
.yllacitnarf dnuora retem eht devaw eH
.niatpac eht ot pu deklaw ztloB
,tsirw sih fo kcilf dna tsiwt decitcarp eht htiW
”?neppah ot gniog s’tahW
”.nekatsim saw I spahreP
dna esacriats larips latem a ot yaw rieht edam yehT
.llaw eht no nroh eht morf deohce eciov dekcinap A
a dna kcab eht ta latrop eht decaf dworc eht erehw rood edis a hguorht edir yeht deretne yehT
.gnitseretni
tahW“ .delworg raeb eht
.pu dekool eH ”.erehT“ .pu
?gniht taht si
.derevauq eciov dimit a ",ris ,stonk 04"   ".tsaf
seenk dna sdnah no flesreh detfil ssertiaw ehT
.retem tnemelgnatne na tuo dehsif dna roolf eht no xobloot eht
.dnuora retem eht devaw estuN
s’tahT“ .enihcam eht fo kcab eht ta trop citsongaid eht otni rennacs sih deggulp estuN  .pot no annetna na dna slenap ssecca wef a
”.em htiw emoC .mrofrep ot seitud evah uoY“
.roolf eht ot llef seye reH
.yks krad ,dloc a dnuora dellor aes ehT
.moor enignE"  ".ris ,stonk 04" .nroh
..rotatceps esirnus eht
.uoy raeh t’nac I“
.elbat eht ot kcab deirruh ssertiaw ehT
.nottub eht deppals ohw tnadnetta eht ot deddon
.draobelffuhs gniyalp morf meht detneverp reirrab kcol mutnauq eht
emoC“ .yawrood eht ni denrut estuN
”.egdirb eht no dewolla era stseug oN“
.toh etihw dewolg eriw niht A
ediseB .sgnittes wen eht retne ot ydaer dapyek eht revo desiop
.reenigne eht ta deddon ztloB
”?uoy lliw ,noitnetta
.elbat rieht ot deirruh taoc etihw eht ni revaeb ehT
,retaw dloc ,elbirret saw
”.thgin ta ees ot drah era yeht
dekool ev’I .gniraeppasid ro tuo dna ni gnidaf era sgniht taht gninialpmoc era stseuG
fi sa yad lla diarfa neeb ev’I“
.daeh sih koohs ztloB ”.dloc saw tahT“
.em dellik tahw wonk
”?kcans a rof emit evah ew oD“
.doog os dednuos gnihtyrevE
,setunim ytnewt ni ecruos eht dnif ot deen
.eguh saw eH .haeY“
pihs eht otni kcab langis cidarops eht derusaem yehT
.decar dnim ’ztloB
.daeh reh revo dnah reh devaw tnorf ni buc regit A  ”?snoitseuq
.dexelprep dekool ehS
.enihcam emit eht fo kcab eht ot tnew estuN dna eH   .deddon ehS
”?taht raeh uoy did ,estuN .thgir s’tahT“
.ezorf dna dnuora retem eht gnuws estuN
.tsetorp yrgna s’revaeb eht htiw cnys tcefrep ni sdrow eht dehtuom eH
”.melborp laer eht
sa moor enigne na otni ees dluoc uoy latrop eht
.neppah ot gniog saw gnihtemos
.erehT“ .pu thgil dna dezzub retem eht ,tnemom taht
.elbanigaminu saw retsnom siht fo rewop ehT
.dnah reh koot dna kcab mih devohs ztloB
.derettahs anihc dna ssalg ,srood eht dniheb erehwemoS
.estuN morf skool gnivorppasid eht gnirongi ,ecalp otni etalp eht dewercs ztloB
.dewob revaeb ehT
.sedir rehto eht fo senil eht ssorc ot dah eh ,emitaeT ot teg
,meht nraw ot tuoba saw ztloB
detfird kcol laropmet eht fi ylgu tog dworc siht
"?ereht nwod no gniog s'tahW
pu tnew reehc tfos a ,mih dniheB
.seye reh otni dekool dna deknilb ztloB
"?ereht nwod no gniog s'tahW .moor enignE"
.retem eht morf pu kool t’ndid estuN
hguorhT .ytnewt morf nwod gnitnuoc saw yalpsid
stseuG“ .citsongaid dlehdnah eht ni deggulp dna
.dewolg stuodaer ehT
.dekrow neve ti taht mih dehsinotsa tI .trap
.seerged ytenin ta revo tneb saw pot no annetna ehT
,reddal eht gnibmilc tuoba thguoht ztloB
eH ”.niaga pu ti kcip ot evah ll’ew
.tixe s’edir eht ta ffo deppets eh sa
,troffe htiw dekcarc eciov siH
”.reh hsinup t’nod esaelP
.tsaf taht og t'nac pihs sihT“
”.yratinasnu si taht wonk uoY“
”?unem eht morf gnihtyna hsiw uoy oD
.pit citengam eht ot wercs tsrif eht devom eugnot siH
estuN dniheb rehtegot
.tsehc ym ni worra na htiw ereht gniyl gnihtyreve was I
.rekcilf ot gninoitisop laropmet eht gnisuac kcol-
latrop eht ni deraeppa serutaerc gnilims fo
reH .reh rof epoh saw ereht mih dlot tug sih ni gnihtemos tub
,dah reenigne eht taht srosnet ytivitaler fo gnidnatsrednu peed eht evah t’ndid eH
”?ereh saw I emit tsal eht dah I tahw rebmemer uoy oD“ ?yeht erew rO
”.moor enigne eht si sihT“
koot eH .latrop eht hguorht estuN dewollof ztloB
eH .deglub kcen sih dna tsehc sih tuo deffup niatpac ehT
.estuN retfa deirruh dna sih ni dnah reh tpek ztloB  .deddon
.knumpihc a htiw rehto eht
,delley snogard eht fo enO
.ris ,seigolopa
daeh sih koohs estuN
.derekcilf lerriuqs gniylf
”,stonk net daehA“  ”.daeha raelC“
.esacriats ediw a fo toof eht ot
tI .retem sih morf pu dekool reven ohw
ehT" ,gnilley enihcam emit eht tsap nar snogard ehT  .deppots
erehW“ .sraet htiw dellif seye s’ssertiaw ehT
”.mih rof eeffoc tunlezah fo puc a dnA“
toN .thgis fo tuo no
.roolf eht ot despalloc ehS ”?ti saw
regnif ztloB .annetna eht denethgiarts estuN sa
.ssertiaw eht ot denrut eH ”.ti evorp ll’I“
.roolf eht otno retaw fo rehctip a gnikconk dna
ti enod evah dluow enoemos ,elbissop erew taht fI .esnesnoN“
esahp eht dnuora gnidleihs eht ni kcarc a si sseug
.aera gninid eht fo kcab eht ta srood gnigniws hguorht deirruh niugnep ehT ”.ris ,doog yreV“
seiromeM .secalp emas eht ni eb dna
.hcnul ekat ot ecalp tcefrep eht edam tI
detcennocsid eH .gniraeppasid elpoep ekil kool dluow tahT
gnilbmuf emitaeT dniheb s’estuN dnuof eH .egdab sih htiw denepo taht rood edis a otni dna tixe eht pu deklaw ztloB
”.su srebmemer ehS .melborp eht si ehs kniht I“
”?rebmemer I t’nac yhW
tI“ .dnuora retem eht devaw estuN
,latem tsniaga gnidnirg latem
yawflah tog dna ylwols dewollof ehS
tnedifnoC .kcab mih dellac ztloB ”.estuN ,tiaW“
tsol ev’I ?did uoy tahw eeS“ .nwod dekool eH
.devom srevel dna sraeg tnaig erehw
hcae dezylana seye siH
.delworg eciov sniatpac eht
,desucof peek ot deirt ztloB
roolf ta dedne ti litnu sriats eht dednecsed yehT
.dekaeuqs ssertiaw ehT
.eveileb I ,eip brabuhr fo eceip A“
,srennam decitcarp dna ecnaraeppa denifer rieht lla
,ogniD mailliW yb uoy rof daer ,hcinniM dieR yb
neht revaeb gnilwocs eht ta redluohs reh revo dekool ehS
.onaclov eht revoc ot hguone gib emod kcol mutnauq eht gnipeek
ztloB .llaw eht no secnocs otni tes sedahs rednu sblub ssalg yb til saw tI
,lenap eht gnidloh wercs esool eno gnivaeL
.tsirw sih fo tsiwt eno ni
draveluob noissecnoc eht ssorca tuc dna
.ssertiaw eht ot detniop dna detuohs ztloB
.lla ta thgif ot teg t’ndid I
iiepmoP ni ytraP fo tixe eht gnissorc demit eH
ehT .daeh reh denrut ehS
.htuom sih ni meht thguac dna lenap eht morf swercs eht deppop ztloB ”.em
.drawkcab gnippit riahc sih gnidnes ,yliratnulovni dekcik sgel siH .depsag ztloB  ”.eveileb
”.taht ekil desserd moor gninid lamrof eht otni og tonnac uoy tub ,ris ,em esucxE“
.dnah a devaw ztloB
.ztloB no kcab sih denrut niatpac ehT
yM .meht fo yna ni taht ekil gnihton si erehT
raeb ralop a yb nepo dleh rood a hguorht deirrucs selbategev fo sdaolmra gniyrrac stibbar erehw kced rehgih a ot debmilc
enoemos fi ,oN“ .daeh reh koohs ikiK   ".tih ev'eW"
,aera wen eht dedda krap eht ecnis shtnom eerht eht
.dnah sih otni swercs eht tips eH
tuB“ .trapa gnillaf saw yroeht demrof-flah siH
.woble eht yb ssertiaw eht koot eH
“.llah gnilbmag eht uoy wohs ll’I dna esolc yats woN“
ehT“ .llaw eht no aera ytpme na ot pu detniop dna delims ehS
ta er’eW .etalugnairt ot evah ot gniog er’eW“
.esolc reh dellup ztloB
naC“ .taorht reh deraelc buc regit ehT
.reward gnidils a morf sunem
meht tnes ecived eht noitcerid eht dewollof yehT
”.enif eb ll’uoy dna su htiw yas tsuJ
”.boj ruoy od dna emit gnitsaw potS
”,stonk net daehA“  .delworg raeb eht
.ybraen llaw eht no leehw der eht tsniaga yllacitnarf dellup snogarD
yrt oD .ruoh yreve steser latrop
”.erofeb naht esrow niaga gnineppah
.dnah reh koot ztloB
”.uoy tuoba gnikniht tsuj saw I .raed iH“
draveluob doof eht sa gnol
.latrop eht ssorca llaw a demrof sirbed dna retaw krad
.dnuora retem eht devaw
,lerriuqs a fo eniltuo eht htiw enO
”.ti tuoba kniht uoy nehw elpmis
,gnineve
”?ecalp siht si
eh ”,gnitsohg fo draeh reven
”.nemeltneg ,redro knird ruoy ekat I yaM“
.retem eht no ecaf sih htiw sriats eht
liat siH .reenigne pot s’krap
.yllacitnarf devaw ztloB ”.won nwod emoC“
.eseehc fo yart revlis a
non dezzub dnah ’estuN elbat eht ni retem ehT
llaf epor tevlev eht tel ikiK
”.esolc eb ot tog
,stnorf citsalp eht
.enihcam emit a si sihT“
woN .ecart eht
,tuo dellac dna htaerb peed a koot ztloB
eno on yb draeh eb dluoc gniklat dna gnippat
.spets latem eht fo seloh eht gnihctac sleeh
pu deunitnoc estuN ”.ereh pu esrow si noitallicso eht tub
,meht ediseb sunem eht decalp retiaw
.reh no tser seye sih tel eH
.pihs eht fo kced eht otno dna pu meht koot taht erutcurts suoirolg a saw tI
.reh no denrut revaeb eht erofeb roolf eht ssorca
”?ssertiaw taht si erehW“
riehT ?snogard dnatsrednu dluoc ohw neht tub
.sdnoces wef a ni enif eb d’eh tub
.depmuls sredluohs s’revaeb ehT
eH .derettam ti taht
eH .thgir t’nsaw eno rettal eht tub ,rehtona neht
.enac reh pu dekcip dna
”,gnihtemos xif ot ereh er’eW .stseug ton er’eW“
.mih revo hsaw feiler tlef ztloB
s’tI .cinatiT eht no emitaeT ta em teeM“
.ylhguoroht strap enigne eht lla deyarps dna tleb loot sih morf nac yarps a devomer
”.og s’teL .ereh gnihtoN .ztloB ,no
dleif tnemniatnoc eht edistuo thguac eb d’eh saw mih ot neppah dluoc taht tsrow ehT .yaw eht wenk
.nruter dluow esion eht
woN" ,dellac ehs reh erofeb enac reh gnippat dna latrop eht hguorht yaw reh gnileeF
.htaerb sih
”?yrassecen taht saW“  ”?riS“
tI .maerd a dah I .won rebmemer I“
sihT .nettirwer eb dluow yrotsih dna
.mra sih revo depard sevolg etihw dna dnah sih ni enac a htiw mooretats a fo tuo deppop tah pot dna
dna psalc eht rof epor tevlev eht dehcraes sdnah
erehT“ .ecived eht
dehsuh saw eciov siH
.rood nehctik eht drawot reh devohs dna
erA .diova ot ysae ,eci fo sniatnuom era yehT
ta delbmert flesmih naht regnuoy
dleh ztloB .egde eht revo denael dna
,ereht pu teg dluoc eh detbuod eh tub
”.em rof soihcatsip fo gab a tsuJ“
htiw rac niart a fo ezis eht xob latem tpircsednon a fo edis eht no deraeppa latrop eht ,edis siht
snoisiced emas eht ekam syawla dluow yeht tub
”.elacs eht ffo s’tI“
”.ecno ta moor gninid siht evaeL
,gnidloh saw eludom tnemelgnatne wen eht tnaem tahT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,seiceps regral fo nerdlihc fo gnorht eht hguorht revuenam ot mih rof ysae saw ti ,knumpihc a sA
.nwod gnitnuoc saw rebmun a ,dapyek eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.redneB ycatS ,efiw sih htiw setirw-oc ohw ,hcinniM dieR yb
.gnar enohp ztloB ,tnemom taht tA
.sris ,niaga uoy ees ot eciN“
”.ruot dediug a rof em wollof ,orez sehcaer retnuoc eht sa noos sa ,llew yreV“
”cinatiT eht no emitaeT“ saw sihT
.drawrof swap sih dehsup dna meht ot pu deppoh tibbar A
.noitatirri htiw dekcilf
,gnihsarht dna gnitsiwt ,nogard a ees ot emit ni seye sih denepo dna roolf eht no llef eH
?nos ,grebeci na nees reve uoy evaH“
.sedis htob no ecnatsid eht otni dehcterts yawllah a erehw gnidnal txen eht ot debmilc yehT
.dnah ’ssertiaw eht dettap eH ”.dnim on mih yaP“
”.elttab cipe tsom s’yrotsih ni htaed eht ot thgif doog a yojnE“
.smra sih dessorc dna detuohs estuN ”?ees uoY“
.trop ot draH“    ”.daeha grebecI" .nroh
.tixe eht tuo delif dna
ztloB .reddal eht debmilc estuN
teprac tew eht deppat enac reH
.rebmemer t’nac …I“
.tik gniyrc reh gnitrofmoc elihw
.oga yad a ekil smees tI
,dnaL eiddiK tfel eh sA  .yalp ot nageb cisum eht sa
,no deppop del eht nehW
.gnirekcilf on saw
”.stnemerusaem dleif emos ekat ot deen eW .gnineppah si
.tuodaer eht fo dne eht llif ot decnavda hcihw sorez eht rof tpecxe daer dluoc eh naht retsaf yb welf stigid ehT
.dnif nac I launam lacinhcet yreve hguorht
s’erehT“ .detniop dna sriats eht pu yawflah doots estuN
dehsur erofeb stnemom nees eb ot erehw on saw ohw mussopo yffurcs
,no ssertiaw eht deviaw ztloB ”.yrruH“  ".esolc
,thgir eht no saw eh
.tibbar eht dnuora deklaw estuN sa dezigolopa ztloB
siH .estuN diova ot llaw eht tsniaga kcab sih desserp eH
nac uoY .cinatiT eht draob lliw uoy ,etunim a nI
etilop os saw ehS
.eniF“ .ria eht ni dnah a werht dna
.unem gnol eht ta dekool ztloB   .tfel dna ,dewob
dna ,teser ot gniog saw gnihtyreve ,setunim ytriht ni
?thguof I eno eht fo ezis eht ees uoy diD .woW“
”.noitanidrobusni reh rof dehsinup ylreporp si ehs ees llahs I
.esolc t'now rood aes
tahW .enihcam htommam eht ta delevram eh tey
’estuN ”?rettam ti seod tahW“  .depsar ztloB
”?gniod uoy era tahW“ .pu dekool estuN
”.yllaunam sgnittes noitarbilac wen eht ni yek ni tup ot evah ll’uoy dna
nodraP“    .dessap eh sa lerriuqs eht dewollof seye ediw
trats s’teL .retnec mottob eht ot neeb ev’eW .pihs eht fo tnorf eht
.deretne dna revaeb eht deppetsedis estuN
ztloB .esion enigne eht ni denword saw eciov ’estuN
tA .egareveb eht deppis eh sa retem eht detsujda estuN  .estuN fo tnorf ni puc anihc a otni top revlis a morf eeffoc deruop dna
,ymra najorT eht tsniaga sevil rieht rof gnithgif erew stseug eht ecniS
”.revo trats ot evah ll’ew ro
.llaw eht gnola yaw reh tlef ehs sa
.eye sih thguac daehrevo
ehcatsum rabeldnah a htiw surlaw A
m’I“ .epor tevlev a fo dne eno dleh
roF .semutsoc nairotciV raew dna
.enihcam emit eht pot no nwod gnimoc saw revel yvaeh A
.uoy nethgirf yam taht sgniht emos ees ot gniog er’uoY“  ”.eniF“ .ria
.derekcilf niugnep eht fo egami eht tub
,delbuod sdworc eht
,gninefaed saw latem gnithgif latem fo dnuos ehT
”.won dleif eht ni snoitautculf gnitteg m’I .ereh gnorw gnihtemos si erehT“
”,elbissopmI"  .stonK 03 .deeps desaercni evah eW .niatpaC“
.ssalg ot otni dereep dna detniuqs
deppord dna eeffoc sih fo pis a koot estuN
tluaf drow eht dehsalf yeht ,eno yb enO
.elbissop ton erew
eht ,estuN rakcarK saw tI
,yldaS .yrenihcam ybraen eht deteiuq tnacirbul fo striuqs wef
eH .teef sih htaeneb deredduhs pihs eht dna
.denrut tub drawrof delbmuts ssertiaw ehT
ehT .tuo delif sagot ni snogard sa hsa dna ruflus fo duolc eht diova ot
tahW“ .egdirb eht edistuo noitartsurf ni detnurg estuN
ti denethgit dna etalp eht ni wercs eht tup eH
.emitrevo sih did os tub
”?su ezingocer uoy oD“
.tnorf eht ta rood a htiw
,ogniD mailliW yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.emit tsal was eh ssertiaw eht dettops dna dnuora dekool
devruc a morf detaname secioV
.deraeppa lerriuqs fo ecaf eht dna