”!rebraF rreH ,eyB“ ro ”!uoy eeS“ ,delley wef A
.ylkeem dias ozneroL ”,gnihtoN“ ”?gnorw s’tahw os
.trufknarF ot tnew eh detaudarg ocsicnarF retfA
”?niaga eman ruoy si tahW“
,gnimrofrep dna cisum gnitirw tpek dna
.pal sih no gnitser aloiv
.ereh wen ytterp llits er’uoY“
.rekloV ot esolc mih thguorb dah ti esuaceb ti fo yromem eht ta delims ozneroL
.ecitcarp ot deen lla uoy tub ,siht yas I nehw flesym gnitaeper m’I wonk I“
.gniyas er’ew tahw wonk t’nod uoy nehw nuf sa ton s’tI“
swohs noisivelet namreG tnereffid eht tuoba denrael ozneroL
.dereffid segnar elbayalp dna sezis rieht tey
.stnanet rehto eht htiw kcultop a dah rehtaf sih dna ozneroL os yadhtrib sih gnitarbelec saw retto elttil ehT
”.taht lla tuoba yrros m’I“
,tsehc sih ssorca smra ynniks sih devaw ylsuoiruf eh sa detuohs xof citcra llat eht
.flesmih rof tunhguod elttil a dna
.cisum rof evol rieht saw daerht nommoc rieht tub
.sdileye sih bur ot sessalg demmir-eriw eznorb sih ffo koot dna
”?taht yb naem uoy od tahW“ ”.ykcul os er’uoY
.troffe puorg a si sihT
.evael ot euc rieht saw ti
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“
.trihs-t wolley dna der s’retto eht tsniaga pu desserp trihs flog etihw s’regdab ehT
.rednefed lufitud sih saw rekloV ecnis ,oot smelborp s’rekloV fo lla htiw pleh dluoc eh dehsiw eH
,morf saw eh erehw fo esuaceb mih no dekcip elpoeP
.ylgums deksa raeb eht
”?taht htiw yako eb thgim stnerap ruoy neht
yrtsudni cisum eht ni esle gnihtemos ro rehcaet cisum a emoceb ot detnaw uoy dias uoy fi ebyaM“
.moor eht fo tuo nar yeht sa
”.strecnoc ruo ta llew yalp yllausu eW“
,wap rehto eht no ,rehtaf siH
noitcurtsnoc ni ralimis erew stnemurtsni owt riehT
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“
”?uoy era tahW“ ”.haey
ynoclab a ot deit eno nailatI na saw galf tsegral ehT
.koobtxet egaugnal a ekil gnidnuos tuohtiw ega rieht srehto htiw esrevnoc ot woh dna
,nwod meht tel t’nod esaelp os ,ytinummoc ruo s’tI
.ylkciuq deilper ozneroL ”,retto na m’I“
,yrekab eht edistuO
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mih fo tnorf ni erocs eht no sgnikram opmet dna scimanyd emos dnuora
”.thgie saw I ecnis aloiv gniyalp neeb ev’I ?tsael tA“
,tnemtrapa sih fo ynoclab eht fo ffo gnignah galf nailatI eht ta pu dekool eh sa htaerb a werd ozneroL
daerb eht gnisahcrup
uoy er’yhW“ .rethgit daerb fo gab eht gnihctulc
.]retto eht gnirehtob neeb yllautca s’tahw htiw gnola
.smra sih dessorc dna deksa eh ”?morf uoy er’erehw ,oN“
,omissaM ,rehtaf sih dna ozneroL dna
.etal krow ot dah dad sih revenehw ozneroL rof kooc syawla dluow
,daeh sih gnikahS
.seirecorg sih dehctulc dna dnuorg eht ot dekool eH ”.yrros m’I ,heB“
”.taht stroppus dad ruoy dna
.ecalp ni gnitlah
,regdab eht hguorhT .stnaruatser dna séfac tseb eht mih gniwohs htiw gnola
”.noisses txen eunitnoc ll’eW .yadot rof pots nac ew kniht I tub ,og uoy tel yllausu I naht reilrae setunim wef a s’ti wonk I“
decarbme yeht dna
”.gnorw gnihtyna yas t’ndid uoy ,oN“
,rood txen devil ohw sevlow yerg hsikruT dega-elddim fo elpuoc a ,skurmoT ehT
”?huh ,sboj ruo laets ot ereh er’uoy ,hO“
”?gnoleb uoy erehw ot kcab og dna splA eht hguorht ekih a ekat uoy t’nod yhW“
”.oot ecalp ym ot esolc er’eW
.derepmihw ozneroL ”,enola em evael ,esaelP“
.yadot niap a neeb ev’I wonk I“
.sexat gnilif dna krowrepap lagel htiw omissaM depleh syawla
,emit tsaL ]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[    .yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.egap tsrif eht ot kcab tnew eh sa yllanretni dehgis eH
.rehtona eno ot denetsil dna rehtegot deyats syawla syob ehT
”.htap reerac sselesu a si cisum woh tuoba niaga klat taht em evag stnerap ym dna sselepoh si artsehcro ehT
.ecnanif ni krow htob yeht dna yenom evah yehT
.hcaet ot tnaw t’nod I tuB“
.taert yadhtrib a flesmih yub dluoc eh os yenom artxe elttil a mih evag dna daerb emos pu kcip ot mih deksa rehtaf siH
wolg nedlog mid a otni denrut swodniw eht morf thgil noonretfa eht ,no retaL
.cisum teehs dna stnemurtsni rieht pu dekcap stneduts eht fo tsom sa
keehc eht no niaga mih dekcep yltneg rekloV
tibbar dnik a saw ehS
.tfel yeht erofeb meht htiw emit erom gnidneps ton detterger ozneroL kcab gnikooL
.ffo mih tuc raeb ehT
.niaga klaw ot detrats dna esac niloiv sih pu dekcip rekloV
,seye deniartnu htiw rehto eht rof nekatsim ylisae dna
.ecitcarp yllautca uoy fo emos ylno taht hguone t’nsi tI
.regdab gnuoy eht ta delims eh dna
,taerg si rebraF rreH morf snossel etavirp gnitteg dna
eripmE namoR yloH eht ot levart ot hguone denrae eserbalaC
.tliug fo gnap rehtona tlef ozneroL  .dias rekloV ”,rebmemer I“ ”.ozneroL m’I“
.nosinu ni rehtegot ”yako“
,tenalPruF yb ruoT dlroW
”!potS !oN“  3 fo
.setamssalc dna dneirfyob namreG sih htiw emit erom gnidneps detrats dna
,gnoS lA yb ”mutcefrepmI supmeT“
.nerdlihc rieht ot resolc eb ot hcinuM ot devom skurmoT ehT
”.nerdlihc yllaicepse ,elpoep rehto rof ecneitap yna evah t’nod I wonk uoY
retto eht ot denrut regdab ehT
,nwot dnuora elpoep dna sdneirf wen ot retto elttil eht decudortni rekloV
.artsehcro rieht ni esle enoyna yb dehctamnu saw otarbiv ot ytiliba riehT
.ma I ,yllaeR .enif m’I“
”--dna krow dnif ot dedeen dad yM“
elbissop sa hcum sa meht tcefrep ot seceip eht fo snoitces tluciffid
”?ecitcarp dna etal yats I dna ozneroL yaM“
?egaugnal wen a gninrael htiw laed eh did woH
.srobhgien rieht dna srekrowoc sih htiw emit eerf sih tneps yllausu omissaM os
.ssik eltneg a htiw
,nuf si bulc artsehcrO
.naibawS ni stlusni erew ylbaborp yeht taht derrefni tub
”.em gnipleh rof uoy knahT“
.gnisaet m’I wonk uoY“
”.cisum eht ot kcab teg s’teL
,smra sih gnixelf dna selkcunk sih gnikcarc
detarepsaxe na denaorg stneduts ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,gnoS lA yb
mih ta sgniht lley ot dedeecorp yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
.denilpicsid erom elttil a eb lla ot deen ew dna
.nwod stnemurtsni rieht tup ot snaicisum gnuoy eht gnilangis
.kool citehtapmys a dneirfyob sih evag ozneroL
!rengierof diputs uoy ,ydaerla namreG nraeL
.dettimda ozneroL
,ecnanif dna scimonoce deiduts ohw niapS morf xnyl a ,ocsicnarF
?efil wen sih tuoba yppah eh saw tub
seuh no koot yks eht sa
– dliuG eht morf selaT ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw
.raef ni delf yeht litnu seillub eht ta seitinecsbo detuohs eh ,tsif a gnikahS
.mra sih debbur dna dias retto elttil eht ”,on ,mU“
.mih derussaer regdab eht ”,enif s’tI“
fo strap eerht fo tsrif eht eht saw sihT      .der fo
,noisicerp trepxe htiw sdraobregnif rieht fo sgnirts eht desserp dna
.moor cisum ytsud eht ni
.tolgylop dna ,retirw yrruf
dnats eht no notab sih decalp eH
.frodlegüH ni tnemtrapa wen rieht otni gnilttes llits erew
,rehtegot krow ot evah lla eW“
rehtaf sih dna ozneroL rof hguot saw tI
.tsoppmal a hcnup dluoc eh os esac niloiv sih nwod gnittup
;deppots ozneroL dna rekloV
,tnaem sdrow eht tahw aedi on dah dna
sgnignoleb rieht pu dekcap yehT
,ebolg eht dnuora morf elpoep dna snailatI rehto htiw dekrow
”.yenom ruo gnilaets dna selbat gnitiaw si rof doog er’uoy llA
yb dessap srac wef A
.wolley deyenoh fo edahs mraw a ni dehcnerd erew nwot llams rieht fo steerts ehT
.detaudarg sreyalp doog eht llA“
.elims a htiw dias yob rellat eht ”,doog s’tahT“
1 traP ,gnoS lA yb
.lesaew a dna tab a yb deknalf ,mih ta detuohs raeb a ”,yeH“
?tseroF kcalB eht raen devil eh nehw
”?gnorw gnihtemos sI
.elcatsbo rehtona saw reirrab egaugnal eht won ylno
”?thgir ,dik wen eht er’uoY“
bmuht sih htiw ecaf s’ozneroL no sreksihw eht dekorts eh sa dias rekloV ”,ay evol I“ ”.dlrow eht fo tser eht ta yrgna ton er’uoy nehw teews era uoy
,nwod sevlesruoy tel t’nod yllaicepse dna
,hctaw sih ta dekool xof ehT
.retnec ytinummoc eht morf ssergit nairebiS dega elddim a yb rood eht no kconk a saw ereht dna
.wap a tuo tup regdab ehT ”.rekloV m’I“
snaf dna sdneirf ynam yrev evah eh diD
.loohcs retfa sessalc noitisiuqca egaugnal dah ozneroL ,emit eht tA
.hcamots s’retto eht otni depees tliuG ”.yrros m’I“
.eson eht no mih dessik dna
namreG ni nettirw yasse na tamrof ylreporp ot woh ekil sgniht elttil mih ot denialpxe dna krowemoh sih htiw ozneroL depleh syawla ohw
,nwot gnimrahc eht fo daor eht nwod rehtruf skcolb elpuoc A
hcihw seirekab lacol eht fo eno dessap syob eht
,eltit eht no detaxif erew seye s’retto eht dna
.tsum I fi slasraeher dnekeew eludehcs lliw I
,derewsna retto eht ”,ylatI“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,oga sraey elpuoc a saw tI
srobhgien sih htiw emit hcum sa gnidneps deppots yllaudarg eh tniop taht ta saw tI
.mih ot txen noil eht ot kool ytrid a tohs niloiv a htiw wor tnorf eht ni regdab ybbuhc A ”.tsum
.taht sees eno on dna cisum evol I
.ffo deirruh dna devaw eH ”.eyB
,efil s’resopmoc eht fo enilemit desnednoc a dnif ot elba saw eH
lortnoc hcus htiw dewob yehT
.skcart sih ni deppots ohw ,ozneroL ot denrut rekloV
.xelpmoc tnemtrapa yarg a ot denoitom eH
.sevael tnadrev rieht morf thgilnus tfos detcelfer yeht sa deremmihs dna deltsur seerT
.gniretlaf reven hctip rieht
.seillub eht ta tuo delley daor eht ssorca morf regdab egral a
.stnemurtsni degnirts dna setulf rof ytiniffa sih sediseb mih dnuora dlrow eht tuoba tlef eh woh wonk ot detnaw retto eht tub
.1061 fo raey dna ,resopmoc
decitcarp owt ehT
.gurhs a htiw detseggus ozneroL
,ylatI nrehtuos ynnus ni iraB fo sehcaeb lufituaeb eht no nrob ,tar nworb a saw resopmoc eht wenk ozneroL
”,os kniht I ,seY“  ”?yako uoy erA“
,meht sdrawot depmots regdab ehT
ytic eht ni rehtegot ffo yad a dneps rekloV dna ozneroL[ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,dekcatta gnieb fo pihsdrah eht etipseD
”.sgnileef ruoy truh taht gnihtemos dias I fi yrros m’I
”.ruoh na flah ni dekoob moor siht evah retnec ytinummoc eht morf elpoep emos kniht I tub ,esruoc fO“
.elims eltneg a htiw deilper ozneroL ”,oaiC“
.emonortem a fo noisicerp eht htiw sesarhp eht hguorht nar yeht sa nosinu ni deppat seot riehT
”.raf taht og meht draeh reven ev’I tub ,ffuts diputs emos yas yehT
deusne gnihgual dna gnittahc fo noitommoc suoromalc A
,mih raen wor tnorf eht ni gnittis sessalg kcalb ,kciht ni retto trohs eht ot denrut rekloV
.yletal krej a fo dnik neeb ev’I wonk I ,lleW“
,lleW“  ”.semitemos krej a m’I wonk I
.erom yalp ot tnaw I tub
.loohcs eht fo tuo delbma dna
emit sih fo sresopmoc rehto ot derapmoc ytirbelec tsil-d a saw eserbalaC ekil demees ti
?loohcs cisum a ot og em tel tsuj yeht t’nac yhW“
.lavitsef nwot ruo rof cisum gniyalp eb ot gniog er’eW
.swap ruoy ni daerb taht tog uoY“
”.ereh evil uoy tel ew esuaceb taht tog ylno uoY
.eri yreif a gnisuoh lwocs sih
.dednetta eh muisanmyG eht morf stneduts rehto wef a otni nar retto gnuoy eht
,doof gniyub ot emac ti nehw namreG ni smret eht lla wenk eh tnedifnoc ,degilbo ozneroL
.swodniw eht fo emos ot depat sgalf keerG dna hsikruT erew erehT
,htam htiw em depleh uoy ecniS“
.niaga revo lla ecineV ot iraB raen nwot llams sih morf gnivom ekil saw tI
ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”?lufsserts os eb ot evah elpoep eseht od yhW“ ,dias dna
,dias dna ,hgis a gnitpmorp
.uoy ot sgniht elbirret esoht dias yeht eveileb t’nac I
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT ta rotide na sa stsissa osla ooragnak der ehT
fo strap eerht fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,hgU .dnuora em htiw meht tuoba yrrow ot deen t’nod uoY .skrej era syug esohT
,dekrep srae trohs s’xof ehT
”,ti fo emos dnatsrednu t’ndluoc I“
.frodlegüH ni gnivil ot tsujda dna
”?ynamreG ni
.no devil tahwemos yromem sih tsael ta tub ,derever sa etiuq t’nsaw dna
.ozneroL ot revo deklaw dna nwod niloiv sih tes rekloV ,moor eht tfel rebraF rreH dna stneduts eht fo tser eht ecnO
flesmih ot seton wef a ni delicnep ozneroL
”.gnihtyna laets t’ndid I“
.gurhs suovren a evag dna
#  .ozneroL rof seiromem teewsrettib pu derrits syawla
.etalap sih etatcid tnecca nailatI sih gnittel ,dias ozneroL
,yltnereffid yrev detca dna dekool yehT
”?srennam emos nrael uoy t’nod yhW“
.grubmaH ni esuoh gnihsilbup a ta ytinutroppo boj a deviecer neleH
.drow tsal eht ta worb a gnisiar ,dias eh ”?thgirla
.xof yknal eht ta pu gnikool ,deksa regdab eht ”?rebraF rreH“
.swodniw yalpsid egral rieht tsap deklaw yeht sa desolc erew sefac dna serots eht fo ynaM
.elttil a knarhs dna daeh sih dekcoc ozneroL
,rehcaet htam a emoceb dna htam yduts ot tnaw uoY“
”?rekloV ,ti si tahw ,seY“
namreG nrael sretto eht depleh stnanet wollef ehT
.dnim sih ni esnes edam yeht taht os rehtegot sdrow eht gnirts ot tnemom a ozneroL koot tI
”.neht erofeb ereh fo tuo eb ll’eW .enif s’tahT“
.9 raoR dna 8 gnaF gnidulcni ,seigolohtna elpitlum ni dehsilbup neeb sah eH
.sraey eht revo evael yllaudarg srobhgien rieht gnihctaw
,naicisum a si ohw
,kcart ffo tog eW“ ,deunitnoc eh
.eman sih llacer neve t’ndluoc ozneroL dna mih devas yob sihT
”,evorpmi ot artsehcro elohw eht rof emit evah ew ,yeH“
.yawa cisum teehs dna notab sih dehsats eh sa deilper rotcudnoc eht
ti dniheb gnihsinimid ylwols thgilnus rebma eht
”.ssalc htam ni pleh eht rof sknahT“
”.ereh er’uoy tsael tA
.eceerG morf rehcaet eluhcsdnurG wen a saw silemehT neleH
.yllufetarg ti koohs retto ehT
,decamirg regdab ehT
cisum eht deyojne ozneroL hcum woh etipseD
.worromot loohcs ta uoy ees ll’I“
.trap ruoy wonk ro ecitcarp t’nod uoy fi enoyreve ot riaf ton s’tI
.skrow lartsehcro nezod elpuoc a dna seceip trohs ynam desopmoc dna
.yltnereffid nettirw erew skram noitatouq taht dna
”?rekloV ,haeY“ ”?ozneroL“
.reucser sih fo ecaf dnik eht ta tib a gnixaler ,deilper ozneroL
.niaga yrros m’I yas ot detnaw I ,yeH“
.noonretfa eht fo ecnaidar eht yb dethgilhgih
.kcul hcum tuohtiw tenretni eht no eserbalaC no hcraeser gniod deirt eH
.liat ruoy gniggard neeb ev’uoy dna yadot das fo dnik gnikool neeb ev’uoY“
ycavirp fo esnes derahs rieht ni rehto hcae ta dennirg owt ehT
,heB“ ,htiw deilper ylsuovren dna derettu eh tahw tuoba kniht ot dnoces a koot ozneroL
# ”.sdrow raews emos uoy hcaet dna naibawS htiw uoy pleh nac I kniht I
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“   :yojne esaelP
.noisserpxe sih denetfos dna
,deksa rekloV ”?sseltniop si cisum taht em llet ot evah syawla yeht od yhW“
,eserbalaC erotavlaS resopmoc euqorab eht yb tlewdlaW saw eceip ehT
.teiuq ylriaf saw noonretfa etal eht tub
regdab eht sdrawot denrut noil ehT