,meht ta lley t’nod I tub tol a sevren ym no teg stnerap ym ,naem I
.tib elttil a dnuora dehsalps eh sa dias
”.dad ruoy evah osla uoY .em dna
.ekoj a ekil dnuos trap tsal eht ekam ot deirt eh sa dias rekloV
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
mom s’rekloV morf sguh deviecer yehT
.mih dednuorrus moolg fo duolc a sa teiuq deyats ozneroL ,kcab yaw eht nO
”.keew tsal deneppah ffuts rehto emos dna yadot deneppah ffuts emoS“
.noisivelet dehctaw dna
hturt eht mih dlot tsuj evah dluoc uoy rO“
”.em htiw tneitap os erew uoy dna ,gnihtyreve htiw em depleh uoy
.yltsenrae dias ozneroL
,sevlesmeht detniauqcaer srobhgieN
”.mih dlot yletilop tsuj evah dluoc I sseug I“
”?thgir ,sevlesruo gnieb tsuj rof deliaj ro steerts eht no dellik gnieb ton er’ew tsael ta tub
,diarfa os saw I em decrovid rehtom ruoy nehw ,wonk uoY“
”.rengierof a m’I taht wonk elpoep ,em raeh yeht retfA
.ytrap gnilkraps a otni frodlegüH fo nwot teiuq
dias eh ”,dneirfyob ym er’uoy ecnis yag m’I dalg m’I
.stneduts eht fo ecnamrofrep eht ta deyojrevo
sdneirf tog ev’uoY
”.enola su evael ot meht dlot ohw ereht stluda emos erew ereht dna su truh t’ndid yeht ,oN“
”,ereht sehcaeb eht ees dna uoy htiw ylatI ot og nac I yad eno yllufepoH
.ynnuf dnuos t’nod uoY“
”,taht ekil dad ruoy ta lley t’ndluohs uoy ,ozneroL dnA
.diputs em llac syawla llits dluow yeht dna
”,ti yb esneffo yna naem t’ndid I“
.srevir era ereht tsael ta tub
.tsehc sih ot swap nevowretni rieht decalp dna dias rekloV
.steews dna doof htiw dnuora nar nerdlihc dna
tuo krow t’nod sgniht fI“ .dekrims rekloV
.snaicisum gnuoy eht fo duorp saw xof citcra taht llet dluoc enoyrevE
.yllacitsacras dias regdab eht ”,sknaht ,hO“
.pu kcab tas dna htaerb a koot eH
.keehc derruf sih no ssik llams a ozneroL gnivig ,dias rekloV ”,eituc ,wA“
thguoht eht ta delims ozneroL
.seye sih dellor ozneroL  .deilper rekloV
ria eht hguorht deraos tepmurt elgnis a fo yrc A
,elbat edis eht no sessalg sih tup eH .derepmihw eh
”.taht evresed t’nod nerdlihC
noom eht fo wolg eht rednu gniyawS
,ylatI gnivael rof niaga neht dna iniraM ied erteiP
wor tnorf eht ni rehtona eno ot ssorca dekool
yrots s’yadoT dna
.gniht eht s’taht tuB“
.nac ew esruoc fO“
.oot namreG ni retteb smret lacitamehtam wonk I ,sulP
.dewollof stnemurtsni ssarb eht fo tser eht noos dna
cisum gniyduts tuoba stnerap ym ot deklat I
,sthgil ni derevoc erew seert dna sgnidliub ehT
,dlrow larur eht ni ereh dednim-nepo tsom eht t’nera elpoep wonk I“
strap eerht fo driht eht eht saw sihT
.sdneirf laer yna dah I fi erus t’nsaw I ,neht kcaB“
# .traeh sih ni edutitarg dna
”.toh fo dnik era teef yM“ .deksa ozneroL
”.tnargimmi na osla m’I tub ,yag m’I taht hguone ton s’tI
”.puorg a fo trap a yllautca saw I ekil ro ni tif yllaer I ekil tlef reven I
,toidi taht htiw ni evom ot dah ew dna emoh ruo droffa t’ndluoc I dna
eerged ym teg I retfa ebyaM“
”.nedrub a eb ot tnaw t’nod I dna fo erac ekat ot hguone evah uoy ,daD“
.uoy ot tuo gnimoc fo diarfa saw I“
”.tnereffid os t’nerew I taht hsiw yllaer I semitemos tub ,taht wonk I“
.ytisrevinu a ot og ew nehw sa emas eht t’nsi evlewt er’ew nehw esu ew yralubacov eht sseug I
.tnereffid su sekam ydaerla taht ,yag er’eW“
.em htiw ereht erew uoy tuB“
,ereh lufituaeb era tserof eht dna sllih ehT“
”.em htiw tseroF kcalB eht hguorht gnikih dekil uoy thguoht I
,dlrow elohw eht ni retto tseteews eht er’uoy ,em oT“
…keew siht reippah mees uoY“ .dias rekloV
.tluaf nwo sih saw ti fi sa gnileef llits elihw
.selpmet sih gnigassam ,dias ozneroL
.egaugnal wen elohw a nrael ot dah I
.ria eht ni doom yzoc
”.daD ,oot uoy evol I“
dnuorgkcab eht ni eceip gniws decap-tsaf a deyalp dnab zzaj ehT
”,taht ekil ti naem t’ndid I .yrros m’I“
suopmop os saw eh tey ’nailatI nrehtuos‘ a ekil mees ot ton drah os deirt eH
snoitces s’tnemurtsni tnereffid rieht ni gnittis
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
noisivelet dehctaw dna deldduc meht fo owt ehT
ssalc htam ni rehto hcae ot txen gnittis erew eW
.uoy tcetorp ot rewop ym ni gnihtyreve od ot dah I ekil tlef I dna
.eciov wol sih ni yldnik dias omissaM ”,rekloV ,eyB“
ecalp koot seillub emos htiw retnuocne yrovas naht ssel a retfa
”,eb ot desoppus m’I tahw wonk neve t’nod I
ecineV ni erew ew nehW .yppah m’I dna
.reivaeh saw enilssab eht dna
,naicisum a si ohw ,gnoS lA yb
.hcuoc eht tsniaga depmuls liat egral siH
.teprac delkceps eht ta dekool eH
.pecib s’regdab eht dezeeuqs dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.noitartsurf fo naorg a tuo tel neht dna dehgis retto ehT ”.regnorts
ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
dnats ot stneduts eht rof derutseg rebraF rreH
.dnaloP dna ,eceerG ,yekruT ekil
”.oot ti od ot egaruoc eht em evag uoy
,srats eht fo remmilg eht dna
.tsaoc eht no erew ew iraB raen devil I nehW“
”,taht ekil ton tsael ta
.tnereffid dnuos I kaeps I nehw tub ,taht wonk I“
,yppah os em edam syawla uoY
”.dekcoldnal t’nsaw ti hsiw llits I tub
.retaw eht morf yawa gnicaf niatnuof eht fo egde eht no tas tsuj rekloV
.htuos eht morf erew ew taht tcaf eht dna
”.gnorts dna gib os er’uoY“
.enoyna ro mih ta yrgna teg uoy nees reven ev’I
”.yako ro riaf mees t’ndid tsuj ti tub
,mih ta gnilley rof nosrep dab a er’uoy taht uoy llet ot gniyrt ton m’I“
”.em ta gnituohs uoy naht
.hgis deveiler a htiw retaw dloc eht ni teef sih deppid dna
.retto eht ta delims dna dias rekloV
”.tnereffid em sekam taht dna tnecca na evah I
,llams eht denrut lavitsef gnirps eht fo gnineve ehT
”.stnargimmi fo dnof t’nera ohw elpoep era ereht ylatI ni neve ekil smees tI
”.em ta gnilley saw ohw nosrep dlo taht dna su fo nuf gnikam erew taht syug esoht ta tespu llits m’I“
”.oot em ot elbirret era elpoeP .struh ti wonk I“
.rengierof a m’I esuaceb em dessarah ohw elpoep eht osla erew erehT
”.ecivda ruoy koot I dna
regdab eht otni denael ozneroL
.mih tsap gnihsur dlrow tnereffidni eht ta tuo derats eh
.ecnarF ni seno eht dna
.dias ozneroL ”,uoy ta gnilley rof yrros yllaer m’I“
.dnuorg eht ta kcab dekool dna
”.ytliug gnileef llits m’I ,oN“ ,deilper dna
”.taht yas d’uoy esruoc fO“
”.ozneroL ,hcum os uoy evol I
”.no gniog saw tahw tuoba
”.cibohponex era elpoep lla ton tub stnargimmi ekilsid taht elpoep emos llits era ereht wonk I ,naem I .elbirret s’tI“
,stset ta meht naht retteb od syawla dluow I
.ozneroL ,enola ton er’uoY
.rehtona eno ot deklat dna dereehc elpoep dna
.dneirfyob sih dleh rekloV ”.seod ti wonk I“
.mih ta yrgna os saw I
fo strap eerht fo tsal eht si
hcuoc eht no nos sih ediseb deppolp retto egral ehT
”.sebohponex esoht morf em devas uoy retfa uoy no hsurc a dah I sulP
.srats eht ta pu dekool dna dias regdab eht
seilppus tra dlos serots eht fo enO
.tnemtrapa eht tfel dna sgab gnippohs sih koot regdab ehT
”.enola evil ot ecnahc a su evig ot hguone llew em yap dluow taht boj a dnif t’ndluoc I
”.no gniog neeb s’taht gnihtyna em llet nac uoY“
.nosinu ni cisum lufituaeb etaerc ot rehtegot gnimrofrep
”,tnereffid lla er’ew ,dias I ekiL“
eussi na evah uoy fi ,ozneroL“
”,ereh gnoleb uoy kniht I dna
gnivael rof em htiw yrgna erew uoy wenk I“
,mih elosnoc ot deirt rekloV
ylatI otni tsaE elddiM eht ro acirfA morf etargime ohw elpoep sseug I“
,mih gniyrrow yb enecs a ekam ot tnaw t’ndid I ,haeY“
”,dnuora ti yrrac ot evah t’nod ew os tsrif stnerap ruo ot ffuts ruo evig s’teL
.eceip eht fo eton tsal eht ta notab sih htiw ria eht decreip rebraF rreH
.skcos dna seohs sserd sih ffo koot yldeirruh ozneroL
.em llet dna em ot emoc ot uoy tnaw I neht
pu depip rekloV esuap a retfA
.uoy ot taht od reve dluow eh yhw dnatsrednu t’nod I dna
,rehtorb citoidi ym htiw evil ot evah t’nod eW“
.ylkciuq dias regdab eht ”,esuoh ym ta aloiv ruoy evah llits I ,haey hO
.guh thgit a mih evag rekloV dna
”?won nailatI ni kaeps ew naC“ ,deksa dna
.ecneidua eht ot dewob yeht dna
.gnihtyna ot noitnetta gniyap t’nsaw tub ,gnipoord srae sih
.rehto hcae ot txen tas ylimaf s’rekloV dna rehtaf s’ozneroL dworc eht nI .delims dna
.ereh eb ot em tnaw yllaer t’nseod taht yrtnuoc a ni m’I fi sa leef semitemos I sseug I“
.efil ym fo tser eht rof ereht evil dna ,ereht krow
.wap s’ozneroL dezeeuqs yltneg rekloV
”.uoy yrrow ot tnaw t’nod I esuaceb sgniht uoy llet ot tnaw t’nod tsuj I“
.denworf regdab ehT
”.worromot uoy ot kcab ti gnirb ll’I“
.dnuora saw esle eno on erus ekam ot aera eht detuocs yeht retfa swap s’rehto hcae dleh yehT
.sthgil degnirts dna
,xob lufroloc eht otni derats ozneroL
ozneroL ”,aes eht raen gnieb ssim od I“
”,retteb neeb evah dluoc tI“ ”!gnizama saw tI“
.uoy htiw gnikoj tsuj m’I ,wonk I“ .dias retto eht
.ssik a dneirfyob sih gniwolb
”.ngierof ssel mees su ekam dluow ti esuaceb namreG kaeps dad ym evah ot detnaw tsuj I yadoT
.niaga kcab sih debbur rekloV
.gnitartsurf os s’tI
”?uoy fo nuf gnikam erew syob emos esuaceb dna
”,yad eno erehwemos rehtegot levart dluoc ew ebyaM“
uoy erA“  .edis sih debbur dna dneirfyob sih ta nwod derats ohw
”.smargorp htam evah seitisrevinu fo tol A
.kcab s’ozneroL debbur yltneg rekloV
.cisum eht ot deyaws rekloV dna
”.rekloV ,uoy evol I“
.reisae yna ti sekam yag gnieb ekil ton s’ti tub ,wonk I“
.yawa daeh sih denrut dna
”,yxes otlom si tnecca ruoy kniht I
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT ta rotide na sa stsissa osla ooragnak der ehT
.ytinummoc eht fo srebmem redlo fo detsisnoc ti ekil dekool tI
”.yadot rof llew deyalp eW
htuom sih tixe dluow taht sdrow txen eht tuoba kniht ot dnoces a koot ozneroL .deksa rekloV ”?won retteb yna gnileef
.retteb era sgniht emos sseug I“
ydaerla yrots eht wenk ozneroL
,egaugnal cimedaca sa emas eht ton s’taht tub ,od I“
.seirtnuoc ynam ni laed gib a si noitargimmi taht wonk I
.tsurt nac uoy enoemos m’I taht wonk ot uoy tnaw I
.meht dnuora dlrow eht htiw ezinomrah sevlesmeht tlef yeht
.noiton eht ta desirprus ,deksa rekloV ”?yllaeR“
.wonk ot doog s’tahT“
sgniht esoht uoy dlot enoemos esuaceb das neeb ev’uoy oS“
.syawyna eno gnikam pu dedne I tub
,edir niart eht gniruD
.kcab devaw eh dna
.uoy tem I yad eht rebmemer llits I
.gninnur t’nsaw taht niatnuof ralugnatcer llams a dehcaer yeht
,iraB raen devil ew nehW
,nosirp ni ro daed ton m’I hguoht nevE“
retal elihw elttil A
egats eht no deniamer rebraF rreH
?hguoht rettam ti seoD“
.gnicafruser tliug fo sgnileef eht dna dewob llits daeh sih
,dias retto rellams eht
.tuo devom ew litnu uoy tih ot desu odnamrA elcnu ruoy taht em llet neve t’ndid uoy taht rebmemer I“ ”.thgirlA“ .htaerb a koot
edirp hcum os htiw
.seye sih morf sraet gnimrof eht depiw dna pu tas eH
.enoyna tsuj ton m’I
,uoy tih reven dluow I .dirroh s’eH“
kcab sih debbur rehtaf siH  .mih degguh dna
.kool lufyalp a ozneroL gnivig ,dias rekloV
.yltneg dias regdab eht
.yltneg deksa omissaM
,lleW“ ”.kniht uoy tahw tuoba erac I“
rehtaf sih ta pu dekool retto elttil ehT
em ot tuo emac uoy nehw tub em ekil t’ndid ydaerla elpoep fo tol a wenk I
”?ozneroL ,yadot reilrae tuoba taht fo lla saw tahW“
.seert dettop llams no elas a dah taht pohs larolf a saw tfel sih oT
,lufituaeb si naeco eht ,haeY“
dad s’ozneroL dna
.swen eht dna noisivelet yb detcartsid ,stelbat rieht no erew yeht daetsni
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“   :yojne esaelP
dezagrats yob eno sa
”.elpoep ta yrgna ssel tsael ta ro
.nwod daeh sih dna
hcum evah t’nod ew taht wonk I
.rehtaf sih dna rekloV htiw tnaruatser eht ta emit sih tuoba thguoht eH
,rekloV tsniaga denael eH
”?niatnuof eht yb og nac ew kniht uoy od ,rekloV“
.dad s’ozneroL ot dias rekloV ”,atsergA rreH ,eybdooG“
.yrgna dna edur os saw eH
,noitnetta gniyap t’nerew rehtaf dna rehtorb s’rekloV
erauqs nwot eht fo elddim eht ni egats tfihsekam a saw erehT
”.meht ot netsil ot evah t’nod ew dna
”.tnereffid s’enoyrevE
.nos ym htiw ynamreG ni gnivil yppah m’I ,sruo si evah od ew tahw tub
deilper regdab eht
ria mlac eht yojne ot setunim wef a koot owt ehT
”,dad ym htiw evil nac ew dab yllaer teg sgniht fi dna ,uoy rof ereht eb ll’I
.ecnarussaer htiw dias rekloV
.taht retfa ecineV ot kcab og ot elba eb reve ll’ew kniht t’nod I
”,nac ew esruoc fO“
moor sih ni yawa sgnignoleb sih tup rehtaf s’ozneroL
.mih no dneped ot evah t’nod I dna
.rehtaf sih elosnoc ot detnaw tub
.erauqs nwot eht morf pu detrats eceip wen A
.uoy htiw eb ot tnaw I dna
”.margorp ecnamrofrep cisum a otni gniog em htiw yako er’yeht won tsael tA“
.msaisuhtne suoicoref htiw dedualppa lla yeht dna
retto retrohs ehT ”.uoy pleh ot tnaw I tub ,flesruoy ot sgniht peek ot tnaw uoy dna pu
.tset rutibA eht neht dna muisanmyG fo raey rehtona tog ev’eW
yenom nwo ym evah I
.yug yrgna ,gib siht gnieb em fo deracs elttil a erew uoy wenk I dna
”,saedi doog ekil dnuos esoht os
htron eht ni snoitacav hcaeb ekil yllaer I sseug I“
”.ozneroL ,oot uoy evol I“
etaudarg I retfa riaper tnemurtsni ro ssenisub yduts osla dluoc I detseggus I nehw ti htiw yako erom erew yeht tub
.teef sih dnuora selppir retaw eht dehctaw rehto eht dna
”,ysmulc taht ton m’I“ .detinuer swap rieht sa dekrims retto eht ”?yako teef ym no pets t’nod tsuJ“
demahsa erom neve dekool ozneroL
”.s’retsam a rof og neve ro snoitidua od tsuj ll’I
.em htiw neeb syawla ev’uoY
.mih ta delley dna mih dellac I
.pu tes ot detrats dnab zzaj rellams a sa
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,gnoS lA yb
”.taht hguorht og ot dah uoy yrros m’I“
”?yadot deneppah tahw dnA“
egats eht fo ffo morf xof citcra eht ta evaw llams a evag owt ehT
”?uoy truh yeht diD“ ”.gnissik erew ew esuaceb
.regnorts yna em gnikam s’ti ekil leef t’nod I“
,dias dna dehgis eH
.dias ozneroL ”,hguoht emit tsal eht eb ot gniog ton s’tI“
.deyalp artsehcro muisanmyG eht erehw
ylkciuq dias ozneroL
.tolgylop dna ,retirw yrruf
wot ni stnemurtsni rieht htiw egats eht tfel ozneroL dna rekloV
.sesnopser drow eno ylno derettu retto eht tub
.seye gnidnatsrednu htiw ylteiuq denetsil dna deddon omissaM
.wodniw tnorf eht ni splA eht fo gnitniap a dah dna
tnecca ruo fo esuaceb em fo nuf ekam dluow nerdlihc rehto eht woh detah I
boj ym tsol I nehW
woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.rekloV ,wA“ .dehsulb ozneroL
.meht dnuora spohs krad eht ta dekool ozneroL
.dlihc rieht tih dluohs tnerap yna kniht t’nod I
.tuo kcab deklaw dna
.oot diarfa saw I“
rewols saw taeb ehT
.daeh sih gnikahs ,dias rekloV ”,detacudenu er’uoy neht
.erutluc namreG fo stsisnoc dlrow ym won tub ,ereht nrob saw I esuaceb nailatI flesym llac I
.ecaf sih no nirg llams a htiw dedihc omissaM ”,nuf gnivah neeb evah owt uoy ees I“
spmalteerts gniwolg yb detanimulli
.gnisirprus fo dnik saw dad ruoy ta tuohs uoy gnieeS“ ”.wonk I“
gnorw s’tahw em llet uoy evah rehtar d’I“
”.em fo nuf gnikam elpoep rehto tuoba yrrow ot evah t’ndid I
.daeherof sih no ozneroL dessik rekloV
.seye sih desolc dna
,steerts niam eht denil srodnev dooF
”.laed gib a t’nsaw yrtnuoc tnereffid a morf gnieb ro tnecca na gnivah taht hsiw yllaer I
.ylmlac mih deksa omissaM ”?deneppah tahW“
.iled eht ta tsiruot nailatI eht htiw tnedicni eht detnuocer ozneroL
.ssalc hcnerF dna hsilgnE rof nettirw ev’I seno eht sediseb ,namreG ni neeb lla ev’yehT
.meht ot nrut t’ndluoc I os erofeb raey a yawa dessap dah amdnarg dna apdnarG
.yaw siht leef ot evah t’ndid I hsiw I tub haeY“
.ereht snoitcennoc laer on evah I
hcaet ot tnaw t’nod uoy wonk I“
mih deniap erutluc nailatI htiw saw eh detcennocsid woh fo ssenerawa ehT
”?ylatI ni yduts ot tnaw t’nod uoY ?yllaeR“
.ecineV ni gnieb detah I“
.eciov sih ni feiler htiw dias omissaM
.rehtona eno tsniaga gnikcor ylwols decnad meht fo owt eht sa
”?ecnad ot erac uoy dluoW“
].tragttutS fo ytic eht ni
.ylthgit nos sih degguh omissaM
.eromyna dneirf ym eb ot tnaw t’ndluow uoy taht deracs saw I
hcnul degrahc yllanoitome na dah omissaM dna ,rekloV
.hguoht selliesraM ni sehcaeb ykcor eht fo naf a ton m’I
pal sih ni swap sih htiw dias ozneroL ”,sknaht ,yakO“
ro tnecca lanoiger kciht a evah uoy fi taht kniht ereh elpoep nevE“
dekool ,taoc remmus sti ot egnahc ot gnitrats saw hcihw ,ecaf siH
”,hguoht noos emityna kcab gniog no nalp t’nod I“
.evael ot tuoba tsuj saw I“
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“
teef dekaos s’retto ehT
.elcnu sih fo noitnem eht ta dnuorg eht ta dekool ozneroL
.eruliaf a ekil tlef I
”.em naht retteb hcum os saw eh ekil detca dna
hcuoc yorudroc ypmul eht no tas sneet owt eht ,tnemtrapa s’ozneroL tA
”.namreG ton er’uoy taht llet ot elba eb dna uoy ta kool nac elpoep ekil ton s’tI“
”?kniht elpoep tahw rettam ti seoD“
em dna rekloV gnissarah erew syug emoS“
.meht dnuorrus dna
.su rof doog eb dluow siht taht wenk I tub
”.esrow neve tlef ti
.redrocmac a htiw ecnamrofrep eht dedrocer rehtom s’rekloV
.debbos ozneroL ”.dad ,struh tI“
”.uoy dlot I fi erom em truh d’eh taht diarfa saw I“
.niaga dehgis tub elkcuhc llams a evag ozneroL
sesnes rieht emocrevo zzaj mraw eht tel yehT
”.em gnissarah elpoep fo derit m’I“
.tesolc eht fo tuo er’eW“
.nailatI ni yasse laer a nettirw reven ev’I ,lleW“
tsehc s’dneirfyob sih otni knas ozneroL
.hgis a htiw retaw eht gnikcik yltneg dias ozneroL
.daeh sih detlit ozneroL
.pu ozneroL depleh eh sa
.tuo wap kcalb sih tup eh sa ozneroL deksa rekloV
”.odnamrA elcnU htiw naht ereh gnivil eb rehtar d’I
3 fo 3 traP ,gnoS lA yb
”.morf emac I erehw dna ekops I woh fo esuaceb
.spmalteerts eht fo thgil eht tsniaga enohs taht stnirp wap tew edam
”.sgniht cibohpomoh yas elpoep nehw truh t’nseod llits ti taht naem t’nseod tI“
.gniht rehtona s’erehT“ ,dias dna
,eromyna meht htiw laed ot evah t’nod ew tub ,seod ti sseug I ,naem I
seigolohtna elpitlum ni dehsilbup neeb sah eH
.s’rekloV htiw sregnif sih decal dna dias ozneroL
,namreG kaeps ot woh gninrael llits saw I esuaceb em fo nuf ekam dluow elpoep rehtO
”.emit eht lla sdneirf ym dna dad ym htiw gnimmiws og dluow I
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“ fo
;syad eseht ylatI ni no gniog neve s’tahw aedi on evah I
”,ti tuoba tegrof dna og ti tel tsuj ot yrt I
.retal sruoh wef a emoh denruter rehtaf s’ozneroL litnu
.tcelaid ym fo esuaceb
.redluohs sih no yltneg tser wap egral a tlef ozneroL sa dias omissaM
”?nailatI ni dad ruoy ot klat uoy t’noD“
pu stnap odexut sih fo sgel eht dellup eH
.ylsuoludercni dias ozneroL ”?llew deyalp eW“
nworg er’uoy wonk I .rehtaf ruoy m’I
”?regnorts su ekam siht ekil sgniht t’ndluohS“
.htaerb prahs ,peed a koot eH
.guh a dna kool gnirussaer a retto eht evag regdab ehT
,em ot edur eb lliw elpoep erehw yrtnuoc a ni ytisrevinu a ot og ot evah I
.og uoy reverehw og ll’I“
”.em naht rehguot tsuj er’uoy ebyaM“ .dias rekloV
”.esae ta em stup taht retaw yb dednuorrus gnieb tuoba gnihtemos tsuj s’erehT
,citnamor a detaerc sruls yvaw dna seton otagel mraw ehT
.od ot tahw wonk t’ndid I dna
em fo nuf ekam dluow sdik rehto eht fo emos dna sdneirf fo tol a evah t’ndid I
.snoinipo diputs s’elpoep tuoba erac t’ndluohs eW
,ecneidua eht morf reehc eguh a saw erehT
,smelborp htam eht fo emos htiw elbuort gnivah saw I nehw tuB
.emit eht lla siht tuoba gnikniht peek ot evah t’nod uoY“
.detseggus rekloV
.tnecca na evah I esuaceb em fo nuf ekam llits elpoep won neve dna
.nrecnoc htiw dellif eciov s’omissaM
”,nalp kcabllaf a sa
,dias rekloV ”,ozneroL ,uoy eeS“
,ecineV ni niaga boj ym tsol I nehW
.erom tol a gnimmiws ekil llits I tub ,od I“
,elttil saw I ecnis revE“
”.erehwemos eb ll’ew taht retfA
nosrep yzal ro diputs a saw I fi sa mees ti edam yehT
.dneirfyob ruoy dna dneirf ruoy m’I
.em fo diarfa era elpoep taht wonk I .yako s’tI“
.stsoppmal ssorca gnuh snretnal dna
.daeh eht no mih dettap dna
ereh devom ew nehW
.rotcudnoc rieht osla saw eh sa
.evaw elttil a evag dna ti thguac ozneroL
.ylmulg dias ozneroL ”,noitanimircsid htiw laed ot evah osla
”?yas yeht did tahW“
”.struh llits ti dna yako ton llits s’ti
.meht htiw sgnignoleb rieht tfel dna
,ytisrevinu a ta cisum gniyduts em fo aedi eht ekil t’nod llits yehT“
– dliuG eht morf selaT ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw ”mutcefrepmI supmeT“ .9 raoR dna 8 gnaF gnidulcni
.pu meht taeb annog m’I kniht yeht taht wonk I
.niaga dnuorg eht ta derats ozneroL
,oot seirtnuoc rehto morf ereh devom taht seilimaf htiw sdneirf evah eW
hcstuedhcoH htiw elbuort evah uoy fi
”,taht tuoba lufwa yllaer leef I .daD ,yrros m’I“
,tenalPruF yb ruoT dlroW
rekloV dna ozneroL htoB
”.nailatI hcum os gnittegrof rof flesym ta yrgna os m’I
daor llams a nwod deklaw owt ehT
.rethgit retto elttil eht degguh eH
”,won retteb era sgnihT
,ozneroL[ ,emit tsaL ]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[  .yrruFoS dna
.pu saw tca lacisum txen eht tub erocne na dednamed ecneidua ehT
,tsehc s’rehtaf sih no daeh sih decalp
ecineV ot ylatI nrehtuos morf devom I nehW“
sedarg ssalc dna seiceps tnereffid fo stneduts esrevid fo edam saw artsehcro ehT