.ztalP ssolhcS drawot kcab deklaw yehT
.dehgis regdab llat ehT
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“
guh gib a rehto hcae evag omissaM dna eH
?das uoy era yhW
seenk eht gnola seloh deyarf htiw snaej kcalb ni desserd saw eH
.efil dna sdnuos yb dednuorrus saw eh tub sgniht tnereffid gniod ffo lla erew yehT
.telbat sih no swen eht gnidaer
taht dezilaer ozneroL
”?yako ,ti tuoba tegrof dna hcnul evah tsuj s’teL“
,nailatI ni ssel yltnacifingis gnidaer saw eh
”.ssenedur sih rof ezigolopa I .ni
,devirra niart rieht ecnO
.dias omissaM ”,lufthgiled sdnuos tahT“
noisses ecitcarp eht otni setunim elpuoc A
.gnihgual dna hsikruT gnikaeps staog eganeet fo elpuoc a htiw elbat rehtona dna
.delbmurg retto trohs eht ”,yako m’I“ ”?ozneroL ,iats emoC .ozzagar ous li e oilgif oim ,hA“
eht otni tliub saw taht ybraen pohs otaleg llams a ot deklaw dna erots eht tfel yehT
”?etal pu ekow I esuaceb ti sI
.ylmulg dias retto trohs eht ”,saw dad ym woh deksa tsuj eH“
,gniklat dehsinif retiaw eht dna omissaM nehW
.sessalc hcaet ll’eh yad eno ebyaM
,selas fo tnuoma tnadnuba na htiw erots gnihtolc a deretne yehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.deilper retto eht ”,thgirlA“
.etib a koot eh sa feiler tlef dna ti fo thgis eht ta spil sih dekcil eH
.tnecca reh morf desseug ozneroL
”!namreG kaeps tsuJ“
.dias retto redlo eht
”.elttil a sseug I“
.elpoep fo sdworc eht ta dekool dna
.eltsac euqorab a dna ,smuesum
.etib rehtona gnikat yldimit
,trihs-t telracs a
,dneirfyob sih ta gnilims ,dias rekloV
?hcnerF dna ,nailatI ,hsilgnE ni gnihtyreve si yhW“
.ytic eht sdrawot dedaeh yeht sa
,enot ymrams a ni deksa rekloV sa llat sa tuoba lerriuqs tuots A
”.esnesnon gnituops saw yug dlo eht taht dias tsuj I oS
.yadot retsis ym tisiv ot negnibüT ot gnidaeh er’eW“
!enola meht evaeL“ ,delley dna
.tuo dellips smeti suoenallecsim elpuoc A
”?yako ,tsrif ydaer teg em teL“
.erehpsomta eht ni llihc thgils a tlef yeht sa
.semit ta hgual mih ekam ot eganam did ti tub
odexut a ni rekloV fo erutcip demarf a dah rood ehT
”,ssob ym si os dna ,peY“
.ledurpS fo ssalg s’ozneroL revo gnikconk
mih evag mom sih yenom eht tuo koot rekloV
.ssenisword fo tnih ynihw a htiw enot retfos a ni deilper eh ”,yakO“
.tnemugra sseldne na stnarraw dleif reerac elbats a redisnoc ot mih gniksa yltnerappA
.setib neewteb dias eh
otaleg fo yalpsid eht dniheb ecaps llams eht ni doots raeb kcalb egral a dna
”,esaelp enoiabaZ dna ,aneramA ,usimariT ekil d’I“
”?rekloV ,uoy htiw wen s’tahW“
”?melborp a ereht sI“
”?oot ylatI morf uoy erA“
.tnaruatser eht fo noitcerid eht ni klaw ot detrats yeht dna
nexiv der gnuoy A
.erom elttil a dnuora dekool yehT
.rekloV deksa retto egral eht ”?ut E“
.deilper retto eht
.lufsseccus emaceb ti dna rehtegot tnaruatser eht denepo yehT
”?won llib eht evah ew yaM
etad hcnul didros rieht fo htamretfa eht htiw laed rekloV dna ozneroL[ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
”?lrig eht s’eno hcihw oS“
.gnihtyreve ta tespu gnileef ,dias retto elttil eht
?otaleg eht ti sI
rallip eht gniknalf sniatnuof owt ehT
,elbanoihsaf ylbidercni dna
”.haeY“ .dehgis ozneroL
.sknird dna sazzip rieht htiw kcab emac retiaw eht retal elihw A .deredro meht fo eerht eht
htiw trihs-t a deciton rekloV
.erips fo mottob eht raen serugif flow htiw gnola
.nworf a htiw deilper ozneroL ”,yako s’tI“
.sikahk dna trihs etihw sih dekaos dna mih no dehsalps tI
?hsikruT eb ot evah lanimirc eht did yhW
.yrc ot gniog saw eh ekil dekool ohw
,mih rof sgniht detalsnart dna snoitcerid htiw mih detsissa I oS .namreG kaeps t’ndid eh esuaceb pleh dedeen ohw
.mih deksa rekloV
meht yb dehsur seert gnihsiruolf dna ,sllih hsul
.selpuoc dna sreppohs htiw dellif teerts ysub a ot
”.otaleg dah ew dna gnippohs tnew eW“
”,nailatI ni s’ti ,kooL“
”,pleh rof reh deksa eH“
.ti ni dekool rekloV duorp woh devol ozneroL
.gnihtyna em llet nac uoY“
.yltruc deilper ztirF ”,VT gnihctaw m’I“
dna serots etuc dessap yehT
emoh deklaw rekloV dna ozneroL[ ,emit tsaL
.ti no maerc trugoy emos daerps dna
.slewot fo elip a gnidloh saw dna
.dias yldnik rekloV ”,taht rof sknahT“
”?neeb yad ruoy s’woh
”,ereh enod m’I taht kniht I“
.kcen sih dnuora niahc dlog yduag a dna
tragttutS ni erauqs tsegral eht saw ztalP ssolhcS
.teerts eht no srehto eht fo tsom naht regral saw taht edoba yrots eno a
,noitanitsed rieht gnihcaer nopU
”,yaw eht yb hcnul rof sknahT“
.elims decrof a htiw ylmlac dias omissaM
,yltcerroc gniyalp t’nerew yeht nehw stneduts rehto ta delley rekloV taht dias dna keew tsal dellac rebraF rreH
ti no emeht hcaeb a htiw gab etot eno morf sgnignoleb reh gnirrefsnart
.elims a htiw deretnuoc rekloV
.setib elpuoc tsrif sih retfa deksa ozneroL
,uoy dlot eh epoh I
otaleg fo puc sih deviecer ooragnak A
niatnuof eht morf yawa gnicaf tas rekloV
.hguoht ,sekoj sti naht rehtar wohs eht ta detcerid erew shgual eht yllausU
.hctip ni esor eciov s’ozneroL ”.mih
.ecnanetnuoc sih ta gnilims dna mih ta kcab gnikool saw rekloV taht deciton eH .delims dna
”.taht dias ydaerla I thguoht I“
”.ton yhw ees t’nod I“
”?namreG ni eb sehtolc eseht fo emos t’ndluohS
.enif od lla lliw uoy taht erus m’I .emoclew er’uoY“
retaews nrow a htiw gnola stnaptaews fo riap a erow regdab rednels ,llat ehT
,daer taht kool a mih evag tsuj ozneroL
.deilper ozneroL ”,gninrom dooG“
dega saw flesti gnidliub ehT
.deriuqni rekloV ”?thgir ’?uoy dnA‘ snaem tahT“
,denruter rehtom s’rekloV
”.yas ot uoy fo dnik s’taht ,hu ,uoy knaht ,haeY“
.sllib orue ytnewt owt tuo koot dna esrup reh hguorht delffuhs ehS
etib tsal sih dehsinif eH
”.ereh boj a dnif ot hguone ykcul saw I dna
”?namreG ot kcits tsuj ew nac ,daD“
.ozneroL deksa rekloV ”?yas eh did tahW“
”.etanoissap neeb syawla s’eH“
.retnec gnippohs a fo edaçaf
.deilper ozneroL ”,thgirlA“
.elzzum nworb a htiw eno eht saw I thguoht I
,mined deppir gnidulcni
”?gnola emoc ot tnaw uoy oD
”.gniht erus ,thgirlA“
,sretnec gnippohs egral yb dednuorrus saw dna
.tnialpmoc a ekil tnemetats eht denaorg ztirF ”,VT
hgis gib a desaeler ozneroL ”.yakO“
”.tae s’tel ,thgirlA“
.niaga si ti erehT“
eiv al tse’C htiw trihs-t a pu dekcip eh sa dias rekloV
,esuoh eht ot yawevird eht dehcaer eh sa enin erofeb setunim evif saw tI
.selknirw ni derevoc yletelpmoc erew sehtolc sih dna delggardeb saw ruf siH
’?namreG kaeps ot nrael srengierof uoy t’nac yhW
.skcals kcalb dna ,eit dratsum a
tnelis deniamer ozneroL
.ecaps siht ni gnieb drawkwa leef t’ndid eh dna
.emit eritne eht gninworf saw ozneroL
sevracs wef a dna spu-nottub emos no deirt ozneroL
dna otaleg rehto hcae def owt ehT
.no srosiv der dna neerg dah dna
.noisivelet gnihctaw saw rehtorb regnuoy s’rekloV erehw moor gnivil eht otni deklaw ozneroL
ynamreG otni tog tsrif eh nehw tes noisivelet eht no gninrut derebmemer eH
ylkeem deilper ozneroL ”,enif s’gnihtyreve ,oN“
.niaga dehgis ozneroL
.seye sih dellor omissaM
.retto eht deksa rekloV ”?ydaer uoY“
,deksa ehs ”?eurt taht si
,setunim fo elpuoc rehtona retfA
.deilper ozneroL ”,thgir eht no eno ehT“
.eno namreG a htiw dessorc galf nailatI na dah ogol ehT
.dedaf ylkciuq ti tub ,krims llams a no tup ot deirt eH
.deksa rekloV ”?thgir eht ro tfel eht no niatnuof ehT“
.retaw eht ta kcab ezag sih denrut eh dna pu desnet ozneroL
”?tnatropmi s’tahw taht t’nsi
.retnuoc eht no sorue wef a decalp dna dias rekloV
fo strap eerht fo dnoces eht eht saw sihT
.rood eht hguorht delley ehs ”!rekloV“
.retaw eht ta derats dna
.niatnuof eht ni gniyalp erew ohw
,ozneroL rof yztlamhcs elttil a saw tI
”,esaelp ,allinav dna ,oihcatsip ,yrrebwarts fo poocs A“
,sgnidliub kcirb eht llA
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT ta rotide na sa stsissa osla ooragnak der ehT
”,haeY“ .deksa rekloV
deklaw yeht sa tub dlrow eht ta gnimaeb ylippah llits saw nus ehT
.moordeb s’rekloV ot yawllah eht nwod deklaw yehT
riahc mra na ni tas rehtaf s’rekloV
2 traP ,gnoS lA yb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ti no dnab latem hsitirB a htiw trihs-t kcalb a no dah dna
steerts eht ni serots euqituob rellams erew erehT
”?gnorw s’tahw em llet tsuj uoy t’nac yhW“
.potpal sih no noisivelet nailatI hctaw eht dna
”?reilrae gnorw gnihtemos ereht saw ,ozneroL“
.deddon omissaM
.mih drawot demaeb regdab ehT
.dennirg rekloV ”!ecalp taht evol I ,looC“ ”.peY“
.enohp sih no emit eht dekcehc rekloV
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.epicer wen s’dad ym rof eseehc emos yub ot iled a ot tnew I ,keew tsaL“
.derewsna rehtom s’rekloV dna
.gniogno llits saw snoitatneserper riafnu tsniaga elttab eht ,niaga neht tub
.rood eht denepo eh nehw strohs etihw dna trihs-t neerg dedaf a ni saw rekloV
.detuohs eh ”!rekloV !ozneroL“
,azzip atirehgraM a tog rekloV .atef dna ecuas ikiztazt htiw azzip lefalaf etirovaf sih deredro dah ozneroL
,naicisum a si ohw ,gnoS lA yb
”.anneiV ot eraf niart rof yenom deeN“
.hgis rehtona htiw dias rehtom
,niart rieht rof detiaw dna
”,moM ,sknahT“  ”.nuf evah ,ereH“
.ti no itiffarg gnitalume ecafepyt a ni
,nevele tsap flah dnuora tA
.tuo sgniht nalp ot ytiliba ruoy dah eh ylno fI“
.sbmurc ni derevoc llits retnuoc eht no dekrap saw recils daerb ehT
.elims yseehc a htiw dias rekloV
.wob dna niloiv sih gnidloh
”,aloiv eht ta tcefrep s’ozneroL ,haeY“
sazzip eht rof diap ylkciuq omissaM
.dezigolopa eH“ .deksa rekloV
lewot a debbarg regdab ykcots ehT
niatnuof eht ni gniyalp sbuc reh morf yawa denrut retto rehtom ehT
.thguoht eht ta gninworf ,dias retto eht
yrotsih namreG yduts ot ereh emac I“
.tsaot sih otno eseehc emos daerps eh sa deksa rekloV ”?tnaruatser emas eht ti sI .esruoc fo ,haeY“
.iraB raen nwot a morf m’I ,seY“
.otaleg fo puc eht mih dednah ehS
.tolgylop dna ,retirw yrruf
.detleb ehs ”!ereh si ozneroL“
.oot dab leef ot mih tnaw t’ndid I esuaceb gniyas saw eh tahw nialpxe t’ndid I
”,gniod saw I woh deksa
,togrof tsomla I ,hO“
?ozneroL htiw yadot tragttutS ot og I nac ,moM“
”.enin ta revo emoc dluohs I taht dias eH“
emit morf enot neerg edaj a otni derehtaew erew seutats ehT
”,enif m’I“ .deksa omissaM
doog leef uoy ekam ti t’nseoD“ .dehgis ozneroL
.retaw eht ta gnirats tpek dna
.no seidooh elpuoc a deirt rekloV elihw
.eciov gnidnatsrednu na htiw deunitnoc eh ”,taht wonk uoY
.enilno deredro eh slevon nailatI daer yltsom rehtaf sih elihw
,deudbus a htiw tfel dna
ozneroL ot denrut eH
noitats dnuorgrednu eht fo tuo meht democlew nus thgirb ehT
.ylatI tuoba deklat ew neht dna
”.peelsa llits s’rekloV ,ozneroL ,hO“
,namreG ni ,thgirlA“
;dedworc saw oitap ehT
htiw selkraps fo ssem hsirag a saw trihs ehT
.swollamhsram derevoc etalocohc hsiloP dna
.rehtaf sih sdrawot yltnednopsed ti dehsup ozneroL
.nrecnoc htiw dellif eciov reh
rood eht no dekconk eH
,lleW“ ”.won yb scitna sih ot desu m’I kniht I“
.derewsna omissaM
.lufyalp dnuos ot gniyrt
”?emoR morf uoy erA
.evael dluohs ew ebyaM“
.tsafkaerb rof revo em detivni eh yadretseY“
.spuc rieht fo desopsid owt eht dna
”.tcefrep si flesmih eh dna“
,sgif htiw deppot eno ,omissaM rof dna
.moorhtab eht sdrawot nar dna
”.ydaer gnitteg hsinif ot aruaL rof gnitiaw llits m’I
.senizagam dna srepapswen namreG daer dna noisivelet hctaw ot elba saw eh
.retto rehtom eht dias ”,melborp on s’tI“
”.mih ebircsed ot yaw eno s’tahT“
”,kcab ti tup ll’I ,thgirlA“
.ni ozneroL tel ot edisa deppets ehS
.su ta sgniht naem gnilley tpek yug ylredle eht dna ,nailatI ni em ot gnikaeps tpek eh dna
ksoik a morf ydnac emos thguob yeht
,dias dna nway a evag eH
”?retteb yna gnileeF“
gnihtolc ydnert tsetal eht fo lla no dah reihsac ehT
.daeh sih gnikahs ,deilper retto eht ”,gnihtoN“ ”?tahW“
.ylderit delahxe ehs ”,seY“
,sbuc eerht reh revo dehctaw retto rehtonA
,omissaM ,rehtaf s’ozneroL
airezzip lanoitidart a neewteb ssorc a saw tnaruatser eht taht grebmettrüW-nedaB ot devom tsrif yeht nehw mih dlot rehtaf s’ozneroL
pu ozneroL depleh eH
.nus mraw eht rednu gnixaler erew dna tuo slewot dah elpoep ynam dna
.pu doots dna stsif otni swap sih dellab rekloV .dehgual puorg llams eht fo tser ehT
sessalgnus kcalb gniraew elpoep
.skcos etihw nialp emos dna
.retaw eht ni teef sih fo htob tup dna tib a pu sikahk sih dellup retto ehT .srekaens etihw sih ffo koot ozneroL dna
,deksa dna reh ot denrut eH
.regdab regnuoy eht ta revo dekool ozneroL
.mih naht reggib enoemos eb ll’ti dna repmet sih tuoba tespu teg ot gniog s’enoemos raews I“
hsilgnE ni sngis ”sguH eerF“ htiw elpoep elpuoc a dessap yehT
.yad nredom eht ni hguorht gniog erew sneet tahw wenk yeht thguoht ohw
”,gnihtoN“  .deksa rekloV
keerG ni gnikaeps ylimaf flow a htiw elbat a saw erehT
mih htiw aloiv sih deirrac ozneroL gninrom yadrutaS txen ehT  3 fo
”.puorg eht fo tser eht pleh lliw taht dna tol a gnicitcarp neeb evah ozneroL dna uoy wonk I
”?gnihctaw uoy era tahW“
.mih erofeb gnitae trats nac uoY“
.ti no delwarcs sroloc dna senil cihpargocac
xof nailatI na saw erehT
,tenalPruF yb ruoT dlroW
.noitats niart eht ot deklaw dna gnicitcarp dehsinif yeht
.esuoh s’rekloV ot deklaw eh sa
.ssik dna guh a ozneroL gnivig ,dias rekloV
riap eht evoba detfird sduolc wef A .klat llams edam
.kcar eht fo ffo ti dekculp eh sa dias eh
.yrenecs tniauq eht ta tuo dekool dna
.guh a flow emosdnah a evag htob yeht dna
.deilper ehs ”,etnein iD“ ”.ellim eizarG“
sgniw legna derehtaef htiw xof a fo eutats a dah retnec eht ni rallip ehT
.ti no delknirps sevael neerg htiw sserd remmus wolley a gniraew won
.omaidna ,iS“ htiw deilper dna nikpan a debbarg ozneroL
”.rekloV ,niaga uoy ees ot doog s’tI“
.]tuo snrut ecnamrofrep lavitsef rieht woh htiw gnola
”?won gniyas eh si tahW“
.deretlaf sreksihw siH
.ti dniheb kcub a htiw retnuoc eht ot pu tnew eH
,emoh gnidaeh erofeb ecnelis ni slaem rieht dehsinif rekloV dna ozneroL  ”.eybdooG“
.telbat eht morf yawa gnikool tuohtiw deddon rehtaf s’rekloV ”.peY“
,daer stsiratiug eht fo tnorf ni depporp
.elims a htiw dias ozneroL ”,nwot ytterp a s’negnibüT“
.suoixonbo dna duol gniniamer
puc a otni otaleg fo srovalf eerht eht depoocs raeb ehT
.rehtegot nailatI ni gnikaeps
.srehpargotohp eht gnidiova elpoep dna
.derevaw eciov s’retto ehT ”.sessalc
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.rekloV ot denrut neht eH
.meht ot pu deklaw dna dessik dah yeht taht deciton
.raeb eht sdrawot elzzum reh detlit ehs sa dias ehs
,trihs sserd der a erow eH
azzip fo etib a koot ozneroL
”.em llet nac uoy gnorw gnihtemos s’ereht fi ,ozneroL“
”!uoy gnirehtob ton er’yehT
.nekat erew edistuo staes rehto eht fo lla
,nailatI ni taht dias evah dluoc uoY“
.taefed fo enot lufyalp a htiw dias eh
.niaga seceip eht ni snoitces tluciffid ecitcarp ot detrats dna tuo stnemurtsni rieht tog yeht gnitae dehsinif yeht nehW
].retto eht ta yawa gnitae llits saw gnihtemos ekil demees ti tub
hteet dettirg hguorht dias retto rellams eht
”.ti tuoba klat ot tnaw t’nod tsuj I ,rekloV“ ,deilper ylderit
.secips hsikruT lanoitidart suoirav dna ,swehsac
.stnemele eht dna
,tekcaj deroloc neerg evilo na no dediced yllanif rekloV
,deksa dna nikpan desunu na ozneroL dednah rekloV
,delwocs regdab ehT
.deilper ozneroL ”,yduag fo dnik s’ti dna ’dneirflrig ytterp a tnaw I‘ ,syas tahT“
ega rieht dnuora sreganeet fo elpuoc A
.reh deknaht ozneroL
.dehgis regdab gnuoy ehT
.retnuoc eht dehcaorppa yeht sa owt eht tsap yawa deppiks dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
.regdab eht rof ti ni noops a decalp yltneg dna
.skeehc eht no rehtona eno dessik dna
demoolb srewolf gnirpS
.leeh hgih nosmirc reh tsniaga dellor nep a dna yb gniklaw saw knim gnuoy A
.niatnuof eht fo retnec eht sdrawot retaw eht dehsalps dna dekcik ylippah eH
”.etelhta lanoisseforp a emoceb reven d’I wenk I tub
tsap rieht tuoba decsinimer dna
.gnihtolc gnikool evisnepxe tey
?tnecca nailatI detucexe yldab a htiw yug eht eb ot evah
,devirra yeht nehW
,gnihtolc lausac rieht fo pot no snorpa etihw erow yehT
.xof cennef hsikruT a htiw evol ni llef ohw aneyh nailatI na saw renwo ehT
ngis draobdrac A
”.og s’tel ,haey ,naem I ,hO
.esuoh s’dneirf sih ot revo gniog saw ztirF taht dna gnivael erew yeht taht mih dlot mom s’rekloV
”,ztirF ,edur eb t’noD“
.yadot tragttutS ni su fo htob htiw hcnul evah ot detnaw eh dias dad ym
scimoc daer dluoc eH
,amard tnecseloda noihsaf dlo doog gnivah dna
.detaefed ,derettups rehtaf sih ”--am ,heB“
.ytrid ydaerla saw nikpan sih tub pleh ot deirt omissaM ”!ecaipsid iM“
.gnineppah saw tahw ees ot edistuo kcab deklaw eh sa deksa retiaw eht
.rotalacse na pu deklaw dna niart eht tfel yeht
.cisum tuoba serac yllaer eH“
sthgiled hsikruT emos gnirahs
gnihctaw llits m’I dna enif gniod m’I“
– dliuG eht morf selaT ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw ”mutcefrepmI supmeT“ .9 raoR dna 8 gnaF gnidulcni seigolohtna elpitlum ni dehsilbup neeb sah eH
”.ozneroL ,ecaipsid im ,hO“ ”.daD
gab gnippohs sih pu dekcip rekloV
,yawa deklaw dna ffo dekcab setaicossa sih dna lerriuqs ehT
.eugra ot stnaw tsuj eh dna loohcs morf emoh semoc eh yletaL“
,dias eh tahw aedi on dah xof ehT
derehtaew dna nrow kool t’ndid roced roiretni eht dna
emoC“ ”.eurt s’taht sseug I“
.ecived sih morf pu gnikool tuohtiw dias rehtaf s’rekloV ”,ozneroL ,gninroM“
”?ztirF ,gniod uoy era woH“
.ciffart toof ssel htiw
.azzip eht fo etib rehtona htiw pu ti derevoc tub
”.ris ym ,esaelp eciuj egnaro ehT“
,reldeiF uarF ,hcum yrev uoy knahT“
staes ytpme fo noitces a ni nwod tas yeht
setik gniylf erew sexof fo elpuoc A
.kcab kool evisnefed a tohs rekloV
.ylimaf regdab siht dnuora gnieb fo gnileef eht ta delims ozneroL
,dias dna mih ot denrut rekloV
”.odderF otaleG“ ,daer tI
.egangis dna ,snoitomorp
”.su dessarah llits syug esoht tuB“
”.hcnul rof etal eb ot tnaw t’nod eW
,mih detpecca ohw elpoep dnuora saw eH
gnikaeps draeh eb dluoc elpoep rehtO
.sehtolc eht rof diap dna nwo sih fo emos dna
.kcab delley eh ”?!tahW“
.deklat rehtaf sih dna retiaw eht elihw unem eht ta nwod derats eH
.deretlaf nirg suoyoj sih dna
”!erovafrep imratuia ,anirongiS“ ,reh ot tuo dellac omissaM
]yrtne driht ro dnoces eht si siht fi[   .yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”!nailatI kaeps t’nseod ehs ,daD“
.nirg thgils a htiw pu dekool eh ”,sseug I“
.deredro ozneroL ”,won namreG gnikaeps ot kcab og nac uoY
”.ydaerla tsafkaerb dah su fo tser ehT
”.mih rof tiaw ll’I tub
.dnatsthgin moordeb sih no eno emas eht dah ozneroL
.gnicreip pil a dah dna retrohs saw tub rekloV ot ralimis dekool eH
.sdaerps elpuoc a dna daerb ni derevoc saw elbat ehT
”?ozneroL ,won gnorw s’tahW“
”?skrej esoht tuoba ti sI“
niatnuof eht fo egde eht no nwod tas yehT
”?iats emoc ,omissaM“
.ssarg eht no mih dniheb nwod puc eht tup dna
.ecaf sih no nirg gib a htiw tuo deklaw retiaw regit redlo nA
.owt eht ta dennirg dna daeh sih detlit eh sa dias omissaM
”,evol gnuoY .teews s’taht ,wA“
.ruf dna sehtolc rieht dehs elpoep eht fo emos dna
.enot mlac a ni deksa rekloV
.selbat rehto eht ta hcnerF dna esemanteiV ni
.derewsna regdab eht ”,doog ,hu ,hO“
”.doog ytterp neeb ev’I ,artsehcro eht ni stoidi eht sediseB“
sreltna sih rof sedis eht no stnedni htiw tah rekcurt a
.mih rof yrautcnas a ekil tlef tenretni eht os
”.ekas s’rekloV rof ,naem I“ .denaorg ozneroL
”.pu desserd lla er’uoY“
,yrutnec tsrif-ytnewt eht saw ti ecnis ozneroL deredliweb
.redluohs s’dneirfyob sih no wap a gnittup dias rekloV
”.yad eno rehcaet htam lufrednow a ekam ot gniog er’uoY
stluda yb detacirbaf smelborp tnaem yllautca hcihw
.daeh reh koohs dna dias ehs ”,ni peels ot sevol eH .rekloV wonk uoy ,hO“
.sreksihw sih rednu dehsulb dna niaga azzip sih ta nwod dekool ozneroL
tsuj eH“ ”?yas eh did tahw ,tiaW“
,thgirb yrev ton enoemos sa deyartrop saw ohw ,kcikedis feiler cimoc eht did yhW
.meht neewteb noitasrevnoc etilop peek ot gniyrt ,deksa ozneroL
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“   :yojne esaelP
ztalP ssolhcS sdrawot delbma owt ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,gnoS lA yb
,senihcam tekcit detsur ,dlo eht morf sessap rieht gniyub retfA
.sratiug gniyalp elpuoc xof dna terref a dehctaw yehT
.nailatI ot gnihctiws retto eht deksa nexiv eht
,seussi rieht tuoba deklat dna
.deilper yliraew ozneroL
”?su dednefed yllautca elpoep rehto taht
semirc gnivlos sreganeet tuoba margorp emos saw noisivelet detnuom-llaw eht nO
.dedlocs rehtaf sih
.dneirfyob sih ot denrut rekloV
.ozneroL ta gnirats erew knim eht gnidulcni sremotsuc rehto eht fo llA
,deksa eh ”?erofeb melborp taht tuoba uoy dellac eh saH“
,gnihtyna gnidnatsrednu ton dna
.pohs renöd a dna
.ti no detnirp enecs tserof a htiw rehtona ot
.sazzip eht gnitubirtsid erofeb ti ot txen ledurpS dna elrohcslefpA fo elttob a tes dna nwod eciuj egnaro fo efarac a decalp eH
”.gnorw si ecidujerp taht nerdlihc ym hcaet ot evah I“
dna ogol s’puc eht ta gninworf saw eh taht dezilaer ozneroL
.rehtaf sih ta detuohs ozneroL
smelborp esehT ?tsac niam eht ni lrig eno ylno ereht saw yhW
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.aera eht dnuora sessenisub redlo rehto eht fo tsom ekil
,efarac eht debbarg omissaM
.nwod tas meht fo owt ehT
”mutcefrepmI supmeT“
”,taht tuoba yrros m’I“
.wen ylevitaler saw ssenisub eht tub
.ti no azzagar alleb anu oilgoV
.nwod flesmih dettap eh sa
”,emit tsal ekilnu
s’rekloV ”,niaga ezigolopa I“
.tnaruatser eht fo edistuo eht no taes a morf evaw gib a htiw meht deteerg
,pirt rieht rof esactius llams a ni sgniht suoirav gnikcap nageb ylkciuq ehS
.srae pu dekrep reh hguoht sgnirrae dedaerht ehs sa moor eht otni deklaw rehtom siH
!yrtnuoc nwo ruoy ot kcab oG‘ ,delley ohw edistuo nosrep dlo na saw erehT
.retaw fo stuops eht rednu seiceps suoirav fo serutplucs dah
”?naem taht s’tahW“
,segdums dna skcarc fo eerf erew egangis dna swodniw ehT
.mih deksa rehtaf sih
.trihs flog a dna snaej fo riap a gniraew moor gnivil eht otni deklaw rekloV
,azzip fo ecils sih drawot ezag sih denrut dna ylkciuq detrulb eh ”,taerg s’gnihtyreve ,yllaer ,oN“
.doom eht pu nevil ot gniyrt ,dias rekloV ”,ytic eht ni emit taerg a dah ew ,haeY“
.elims a htiw dias ozneroL
.llips a dah ew ,oN“
,dias dna kool desirprus a evag ehS
.ytivitca loohcs retfa na tsuj si artsehcro ehT
.yldetarepsaxe deilper eh ”,simirK neeT“ .dedlocs dad sih ”!ztirF“ ”.gnihtemoS“
.denialpxe ozneroL
”,taht ekil dad ruoy ta lley t’nod ,no emoc ,ozneroL“
.delley eh ”!daD ,luferac eB“
.llew sa edis sti no revo ti dekconk yllatnedicca tub gar a rof kcapkcab sih otni dehcaer eH
.mih derussaer ehs ”,su demrofni eH“
.hctaw sih dekcehc eH
,noitces s’nem eht otni gniklaW
serutcip gnikat stsiruot erew erehT
”.hcnul evah ot stnaw dad siH
.elkcuhc suovren a htiw dias rekloV ”,haey hO“
”,os yas uoy fi ,thgirlA“
tsaot fo eceip a debbarg ozneroL
depoleved slliks namreG sih sA
,su rof pu doots ydal taht tuB“
.stnaruatser dna serots htiw teerts nairtsedep a nwod neht dna
.otaleg fo puc sih ta dekool ozneroL
”.gnorw gnihtyna od t’ndid uoy ,yrros eb ot evah t’nod uoY“
.sregnif sih gnitegdif detrats ozneroL
,buc a sa scitsanmyg devol I
.seye sih debbur eH
.laedro eritne eht morf ysaeuq tfel hcamots s’ozneroL
fo strap eerht fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”,looc si segaugnal rehto ni sgniht gnivaH“