zaC sa tnenimorp erom hcum ti edam gnicneirepxe yltnerruc saw eh hgih rohci eht
.tsehc reh fo emos neve
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
;taht tuoba yrrow t’nod uoY“
aera eht ta ylgnicitne gnikcil erofeb kcep a redluohs reh evag ylpmis eh ,tsrif tA
.sih ot spih reh gnignirb
.tuoba ehtirw sgel reh leef neve dluoc eH
,ydaer gnitteg ni emit on detsaw zaC
.htaerb rettoh hcum sih htiw
,niks sih gnola deggard ralloc ekohc eht fo sgnorp eht sA  :ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  zaCuggiP yb
.tuo polf ot eugnot ytfeh a rof
dluoc ehs sa ediw sa daerps sgel reh peek ot dah ehs ,woN
.sevlac eritne reh deppirg eh ,on—
”~.ti htrow egamad laretalloc eht gnikam tuoba yrrow uoy
.ylleb gnitalfni sih ni ylivaeh gniloop
”?enod er’uoy kniht uoy oD“
.sgel reh neewteb mraw dna
ylgnilttesnu sih—
dehctiwt spih sih sa mih morf tuo delttar tnurg yvaeh A
.mih ta pu dekool ehS
,ssenregae dewener htiW
,htuom sih gnipiW
elttil a tog I…I ,yrros m’I…I-
”tsaeB A oT gnidneT“ saw sihT
.reh ta kool neve ot suovren oot saw eh
,reh ta deddorp tI
,taorht sih elddarts ylkciuq ot htgnerts eht dnuof ehs ,erons ot nigeb reh ediseb tsaeb eht draeh ehs nehW
,reh dniheb knis deb eht tlef ehS
desirprus tsomla saw ehs ,taht ekil reh gnippord tsuj zaC morf etari ylsuoivbo
.dnim sih deduolc taht citocran rengised a ekil tnecs reh gniffuh yllacitcarp
,hsols a dna elgrug a htiW
.reh ta kool mih gnikam dna
tsuj ,rof gnitiaw uoy er’tahw…kcuF“
.shgiht reh neewteb ti gnihcnelc
!em ot ti evig tsuj ,ti nmad doG
demees taht wam a htiw ylleb ot ecaf saw ohw
regnuh lautca neewteb esrap ot drah saw taht kool yrgnuh a saw tI
.ylfeirb ylno tub ,detsagrebbalf tsomla saw zaC ”.tae ot steg eh
,yrros saw eH .seye elprup
?uoy did ,ralloc siht rof hcum oot yap t’ndid uoY“
.krow ot tnew ylkciuq eugnot sih elihw niorg reh ta gniffuh
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,zaCuggiP yb
selkna reh deppirg sdnah sih sa raob eht rof hcum oot gnihctiwt detrats evah tsum ehS
.gniliec eht otni gnipmub morf daeh sih pots ot reffub a sa
”.gnillor teg ew ecno gnol tsal ton thgim tI
,od dluoc raob eht taht gnihtyna tuoba deirrow ton saw eixrop ehT
,snoitasnes fo esuap eht nI
ydob sih dedoolf edisni etisarap eht sa
.evitcepsrep otni ezis sih tup yllufecrof erom reh gnidloh sdnah sih gnivaH
.kcen sih tsniaga sgnorp eht gninethgit
.stnemom ni emit tsrif eht rof ria hserf emos ehtaerb reh gnittel dna edis reh ta gniyal
htworg fo egrus a sa sredluohs sih gnillor
.kcab reh no detser ylleb sih sa
.rorroh dna ysatnaf sa hcus serneg rehto otni snoziroh rieht gnidnapxe neeb sah tub
,nwod dennip ylsuoenatlumis saw ehs erofeb thguoht eht hsinif ot dewolla neve t’nsaw ehS “-
,nwod delttes ti litnu yawa eugnot s’wam eht gnihsup dna
.niaga drawrof dehsup ylwols dna
redluohs reh desaeler zaC ,nwod delkcirt doolb reh sA
,rehtegot ralloc eht fo sdne owt eht werd taht
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ti fo egatnavda ekat ton did ehs fi denmad eb dluow ehS
emit on detsaw zaC  ”~.pu taE ~.no oG“
sgel reh gnixaoc
,deneppah tahw fo wolgretfa eht nI
tnecs reH .reh ni ylno
tuons sih erofeb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.mih morf tuo toohs muc fo tsrub retfa tsrub leef dluoc eH .gnimsagro elihw
”tsaeB A oT gnidneT“   yojne esaelP
.pu rekrop eht tuhs ot yaw doog a saw ti tub ,ton ro retsnom
demrof maes a erofeb
.kcoc s’goh eht yb nepo daerps gnieb flesreh gnileef osla elihw
.tug nellows sih revo mih fo ees dluoc ehs tahw ,lleW
.kcen reh nwod liart doolb fo elkcirt thgils a dehctaw eh sa
.etsat a tog eh sa gnol sA
eno siht piks nac uoy
.tsurht erom eno htiw dehcnelc
.ti rof pu ekam naht erom dluow
rehtar ro ,nihc sti ta debbur okieK
,tem tsrif yeht nehW
”~.yrgnuh erew uoy thguoht I
.yaw dab a ni gnilggurts reh leef t’ndid zaC tub
.taht fo erus edam ehs
,kcen reh ta ssik zaC leef ot okieK rof gnol ekat ton did tI
niahc fo pool eht no dellup dnah regae oot tsomla na sa
”.yrassecen ton yletulosba si sihT“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,detrats neve ton dah yehT
,krow hsitef citore ni yltsom selbbad taht retirw tsiybboh ,yranib-non a ,zaCuggiP yb
.gnihtyna yas ot deen t’ndid eh
,yllebrednu s’raob eht
.laref enog dah eh fi sa
.meht htaenrednu roolf eht otno tuo gniwob yllacitcarp sserttam eht
.murd a ekil tlef tI
reh ta dekool dna
.ni kcab flesmih dehsup eh sa
.neppah ot tuoba saw tahw fo gnilkni na dah ydaerla ton dah ehS .tsomla ylnO
trapa meht tilps dna
,sgel s’eixrop eht neewteb gnivid yllacitcarp zaC yb dewollof ylkciuq saw trons A  ”~.gip
spil sih delruc elims suoived A
,redluohs eritne reh deflugne yllacitcarp htuom siH
”.’etuc‘ rof ereh ni emoc t’ndid ew wonk uoy
,taht rof yap ylbaborp lliw eH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.thguoht ehs gniht dnoces eht saw tahT .lluf…oS
”!od I sa hcum sa uoy sevol eh ekil skool ,heH“
,shgiht reh otni knus hteet sih sA
,reh raeh t’ndluoc eh elihW
.kcuf eno morf tsuj dna
seye sih ni ti ees dluoc ehS   ”…heh ,flesym fo daeha
,detubirtsid erom tahwemos thgiew sih teg ot elba saw eh
.mih ot gnitcidda tub reh ot enadnum
.eloh reh ta esaet dna skeehc reh neewteb hsup ot eugnot sih gnitcepxe ton saw ehS !KCUF
.mih dnuora hcnelc reh tlef eh ,daetsnI
,ruf tsehc s’raob eht ot pu dnah eerf reh thguorb okieK
,lausu sa ,niap yb denedlobme ,zaC
,tnetnoc s’traeh sih ot dednuop eH
,stnemom gniwollof eht ni ,nehT
dnuof tsuj eh ro tahT
,deb eht no saw eh ecnO
tsirw sih no deraems doolb tnecsediri
.leef reh edam ti woh desnes eH
tug sih fo edis rehtie no sgnaf fo tes a sa gniraeppa
,eugnot sih esu ot detrats eh nehw ,revewoH
ecnedive elbisiv ylno ehT
ydob regral won s’raob eht fo gnileef eht htiw detniauqca teg ot emit dah ylerab ehS
.deb eht no nwod reh tes dna denrut eh sa
.swollip emos no pu depporp flesreh tpek dna
;hguoht ,retteb wenk eH
,kcen s’eixrop eht otni gninael
.deticxe os ydaerla saw eh dna
tfos os tlef tub mrif os dekool tI
.yleerf ecnuob kcoc sih tel ot pu ylleb sih gnitfeh
eixrop eht sdrawot htrof dellews dna degrus tI
kcab spih sih devom eh sa
”tsaeB A oT gnidneT“
.kool elbanoitseuq a eixrop eht evag zaC
,smra sih ni dexaler eixrop eht nehW
.eb ot gniog saw ti kciht woh rof deraperp ton saw ehs tub
htmraw esnetni na tlef eh ,ydob redaorb
I“ .gnikniht tuohtiw pu dekcil eh hcihw
.tnorf sih no reh gnitser elihw
,erofeb ydeerg demees zaC fI
.tnedaced ylpmis saw reh tuoba gnihtyrevE
,sniwt htiw mret lluf yllacitcarp saw ehs ekil dekool ehS
thginot taht depoh eh tub
,zaC otni pu dekcab okieK
.tsaeb eht ta pu dekool ehs sa
,teef reh ffo reh peews ot evitaitini eht koot zaC
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.ni knis hteet sih gnittel erofeb
.siht rof meht deen ot gniog saw ehS
,raob eht ta pu dekool okieK sA
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.nrut a koot sgniht
prahs gnihtemos sa
.yppup deticxe na ekil reh ta deppal eugnot eht sa
,ralloc sih fo niahc ward eht ta deknay okieK
,yrgnuh si ybab ym fI ’.pu taE‘ ,dias I“
,pu taE“ .sgel reh gnidaerps ,shgiht reh revo sdnah reh nar ehS
tsiaw sih gnilddarts otni
.reh revo flesmih denoitisop zaC sa tlef sserttam eht woh wenk ehs
.gnitallitit tib a saw ti ,gnihtyna fI
sgnorp sti gninethgit
.htuom reh fo dewolla ehs tahw derolpxe eh sa rehtegot spil rieht gnisserp
noitamrofsnart eht morf gnitnap derobal s’zaC morf trapa tnelis saw moor ehT
?dehsinif ydaerla
,ecarg elttil htiW
reh dnuora hsiuqs ylleb taf s’zaC gnileef
.noisseccus kciuq ni rehto eht retfa eno syekcih gnivael ylpmis saw eh litnu
.hctib gib a si siht kcuF
rohci kcalb fo slriws erehw
.gnileef eht dehctam ylniatrec ecnaraeppa eht
.deb eht ot reh deklaw eh sa ylmrif reh dloh ot erus edam eH
.dluoc yeht moor elttil tahw htiw ylleb sih bur ylteews sdnah llams reh tlef eH
,smra sih nwod delevart htworg sihT
,rellat sih hguorht desruoc taht rewop eht ni delever eh sA
tsehc elpma reh ssorca doolb eht gniward
ssik hcae htiw redrah gnikcus
.ylleb sih fo pot no reh gnidloh elihw
tressed etaciled tsom ,tsenif eht saw ehs ekil
elggig ot dah okieK litnu
.elohw pu reh elbbog ylbaborp dluoc eh ,ot detnaw eh fI
,reh revo gnidnats tub
meht detfil eh sa ssam elppus htiw pu meht gniklub
seenk reh no tog ehs ,revo gninruT
,sgel reh neewteb regnol on
.niks reh decreip
.gniyas saw ehs tahw wenk ehs
ecaf sih erofeb llub gnikcub a ekil erusaelp fo sevaw eht gnidir
,nwod deid yllanif ti nehW
,tnemssarrabme fo tuo yawa dekool tsomla raob eht nehW
.kcen reh morf ffo gnitfil
”~?bmuht ruoy rednU“  ”~.taht ekil etuc ytterp kool uoy…wonk uoY“
.thguoht ehs gniht tsrif eht saw tahT .tihs yloH
ksut sih ta deppal eugnot s’zaC
.deb eht otno nwod pord reh tel eh
.ecaps etihw eht dellif ydaerla
.mih htaenrednu morf tuo gnikeep tsuj teef s’eixrop eht saw esac eht gnieb ton taht fo
,dehcnilf raob ehT
,mrof lacisyhp ekat ot nageb neht etisarap ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,okieK ffo flesmih detfil dna hgis a tuo tel zaC
,nwod gnikool yllaniF .evitisnes oS
etsat reh gnirovas fi sa
uoy erA“ .ekaw rieht ni liart gnitaidar a gnivael
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dah eh kool eht yb desirprus tsomla saw okieK
,erusaelp yna morf demaercs ehs fI
.ylleb reh ta tlef sdnah suoiruc reh
.redluohs reh detcepsni okieK sa
ruf sih ta dehcnelc sdnah reH
rethgual reh gnidloH
,did ehs…lleW
.drah oot ti gnitib morf pil reh decreip tsomla ehs
,nwod decart dnah reH
,htomeheb eht htaenrednu delffum saw ti
.ytpme tlef ehs ,ylnedduS
.dab oot gnihton tub ,rednet ylthgils tlef tI
si yrots s’yadoT dna
seno deddil-flah s’raob eht htiw tem seye s’okieK
zaC ees ot pu dekool okieK
,sserttam ynoihsuc eht otni kcab dial ehS ”~?gnorw s’tahW“
.borht mih gnileef
.sregnif reh neewteb ffulf fo tfut eht htiw gniyalp
.liof munimula fo eceip a tsuj saw ti ekil ffo ti erot dna
,drow eht fo esnes yreve ni suonevar saw eH
kcen reh ta deffuh
,okieK ta degnul zaC
hsup hcae htiw repeed flesti gnixaoc ylwols
,dnah eno htiw okieK pu depoocs yllacitcarp
,rohci suocsiv htiw
.rednet saw hself reH
raj eikooc eht ni dnah sih htiw thguac dlihc a ekil dekool eH
thgiled neknurd ni denaom zaC
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
,seye s’raob eht ta pu gnikooL
.erusaelp ni lworg htob meht gnikam wohemos
ralloc sih deppirg eh nehw
.skeehc reh neewteb flesti gnitser saw esle gnihtemoS
.ytisoiruc deugirtni ni kool ylno dluoc ohw
,tsiaw s’eixrop rellams eht dnuora sdnah sih depparw
.railimaf oot lla
:deregnil llits doolb reh fo etsat ehT
mih morf gnitaidar taeh eht leef dluoc ehS
.reh rednu steehs eht dehcnelc ehs sa
,si siht sa etuc sA“
.feeb fo xim 02/08 na htiw
,sevruc reh erolpxe sdnah reh gnittel
.erised lanrac dna
.pu reh krow ot moor daeh sih evig ot
.yrgnuh os dekool llits eh tub
.wolla dluow tfeh sih eveirper elttil tahw ti gnivig
”?-assecen si siht kniht yllaer uoy oD“
sserttam eht gnipmuh ylpmis saw retsnom siht kniht dluow yeht ,won thgir ni klaw ot erew enoemos fI .redraH
.sgel reh fo edisni eht ta gnippin ni thgiled taerg
sesnes sih gniflugne
psag neddus a tuo tel neht ehS
deppots gninettaf s’zaC ,yllaniF
trohs tuc saw thguoht s’zaC
”~?thgir ,yrgnuh llits er’uoY“
;seye sih ni kool eht was okieK
tuo ffup tsehc sih edam
.hguoht ,kcab gnidloh saw eH
.hcamots sih hguorht etaidar
okieK morf yawa sehcni
deb eht hsurc tsomla dna tis ot dnuora gninrut
.gnihcneuq saw doolb reH .gnitacixotni saw