,ytisoiruc lufyalp yb dekals tub
stra krad reh ssap ot ytinutroppo eht rehtom degnartse sih deined yltnemehev dah eh
.tneconni yllufeow os rethguad sih gnipeek ta ssentpeni nwo sih esruc dluow eH
.syad sih fo tser eht rof tliug fo bmot a ni flesmih gnilaes
.yrrow htiw gnilknirc sreksihw sih dnuof eh
.llehs sselesromer reh nihtiw peed dehctah nalp a dna stug reh derrits eliug fo revils gninnuc A
.deltrats eb ot reh gnitcepxe
elat reh ,snoitpeced lla ekiL
niur gnimaelg s’yerp reh morf yawa htoot nori talf eht degdun ehS
,gnuoy reh ekilnu rof
",ecnaegnev fo su lleT"
,ot mialc dah namuh rehto on sesnes htiw gninetsiL
”looF detraeH-tfoS a fo
,nossel nwo sih nrael ot gniliaf dehsirep flow teews ruo oS
.epacse ehs did ytirahc sih yb ylnO
.evarg sih ot mih esahc won dluow
rethguad nekcirts-rorret sih dna flesmih degaussa eh erofeb ton tuB
.deen yna ereht saw regnol on
.yldeirrow deirc lrig eht ,amdnarG"
.smrahc decitcarp rednu deirub snoitnetni tnelovelam
,tliug yb tner eno
,sloof htob nopu dehgual evah dluow ehs ,luos a hctiw daed eht daH
,sselfles hcuS
tcaP elbatirahC ehT“yojne esaelP
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,rehtar rednow dluohs ew sessap emit sA
,ylmraw mih deteerg buc namuh eht
.evah dluoc ehs egdelwonk lufrewop tsom eht
,maor lrig gnuoy eht tel eh os dnA
esirprus sih ot hcuM
.luos elbatirahc a no thgiew s’traeh tfos eht ylno
!eviecer dluow lrig eht ecnarongi morf ecnareviled gnitcaxe tahW
,nwod mih gnirb ot swalc ron hteet rehtien dedeen dniknamuh fo hcterw sselesnefed tsedlo ehT
.nori yb rehto eht
,eert gnirutcarf a ekil ,sraey sseltnuoc htiw delrang dna tneb dna depoots saw ehS
slrig efas fo yldnuos gnimaerd
,nos sseltfihs nwo s'rehtomdnarg eht ,rehtaf hsiroob a dah lrig ehT
.dnah gnihctulc a fo selkcunk eht morf regnif knip teews a
.saelp s'hctiw eht ni worros yb dehcuot
.deraperp nossel reh dnif ot devirra lrig ehT
,dettolp rehtomdnarg eht traeh kcalb reh ni ylterceS
.floW_pilS@ dnuof eb nac ohw floW-
.shguob ’sti htaeneb gnikrul staerht gnigavar eht ot yerp llaf noos dluow
.tliug fo swaj eht ni tew gnurw ,rehtaf lufraet
ned nedoow tiperced a ot gnimoc erofeb sllaftip rof daeha htap dekoorc eht detuocs dna
,deransne seihtapmys sih htiW
.desufnoc ,dias lrig eht ",amdnarG"
.ecarg rof deggeb seye tsiom dna spil gnireviuq
tcnitsidni epahs sih
;noitamitse s'flow eht ni deed elbon a saw sihT
rethguaddnarg eht roF
,lleweraf edab eh oS
,ksuh delrang reh dehsang yltnatculer flow detas ydaerla eht ,drow sih gnipeeK
",oot eson gib a tahw dnA"
,rehtomdnarG reh gnihsinif rof elbisnopser saw tserof eht fo erutaerc emos taht egdelwonk gninekcis eht
.detneler ylhsiloof eh
./flow-pils/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www//:sptth ta krow trohs sih morf stprecxe dnif nac uoy dna levon tsrif sih ta yawa gniggulp llits s’eH
.eil dirroh reh hctam ot werb gnizylarap a htiw
,lrig tneconni ehT
,nepo snamuh rof traeh tfos s'flow eht raet ot htoot nori eht desu dna
,deliopsnu s'rethguaddnarg eht fo tnecs gnidloH
,llew wenk rehtaf ruoY"
.werb yna naht regnorts egnever dedoolb-toh htiw
.sevlow fo ycrem ro ytilibon eht fo selat llet regnol on yehT   floW-pilS yb
.sesruc dessih htiw mih detnorfnoc dna
.deerga ylidaer flow eht ,ecneconni
.ned eht ni elam tsedle eht yldas won
.leef t’ndluohs uoy sgniht leef uoY
.senaw sgniht fo redro eht rof tcepser ruoy dna llud sesnes ruoy ,spord draug ruoy ,deruoved kcub gnirps eht htiW
,tnahpmuirt ruO
.esuoh ditef eht morf lrig eht gnisahc ,depael flow ehT
.yawa yllufecaep deppils ehs sa ylici delims dna thguard rettib a knard
ssenhsiloof sih rof tliuG
,ega fo seinoga gnidnenu eht yb teseb ,saw ti sa tfel emit elttil os dah ehS
,ycrem fo noissim a no emoc dah eH
.ees uoy ,tserof eht fo raef on dah rethguaddnarg roop ehT
,yltnatropmi eroM
,elims yci suoiruc
,ecarbme ’ecneconni morf deppir yllufniap ,rethguaddnarg eht dnA
s'rehtomdnarg a dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,emaN rohtuA yb ”eltiT yrotS“ saw sihT".setirovaf ym era esoht
.rethguaddnarg reh gninrecnoc eno
,sih deraef dnik reh gniwonK
.sgar gniknits dna senob dewehc tsgnoma
.nur ot nehw wenk
llew wenk rehtomdnarg eht dnA
,flow gnipeels ruo nopu emac eH
,enola sdoow eht levart ot hsiloof saw kcots yna fo buc A
.dehsiugnal tsedle s'lrig eht detcepsus eh erehw
sevlow fo rorret ni emoh delf rethguaddnarg ehT
.roivas gnilliw reh rof esod gnilppirc a rehtar tub
,noitseuq ni delworg dna esolc deklats flow eht
,repmihw did flow ruO
,tor deird-retniw
,yrrow teews sih ni flow ruO
.srobal sti fo denialpmoc hcamots sih sa neve edirp ni deksab eh
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
pilS         ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
.doof fo tellug warts a gniraeb
.rial s'hctiw eht tuoba ti gnillips
"!deniag ev’uoy hteet gib tahW"
,rehtomdnarg reh rof tpecxE
,dlihc sseleliug eht ot no
",ecnaegnev fo selaT"
,ylraed mih deknaht rehtomdnarg ehT
.mrah on dednetni eh taht deyevnoc rotaderp eht ,strons wol nI
.lla retfa ,kcis dna dlo nwo rieht fo erac ekat sevlow
ekas s’regnuh rof gninrom taht dehctapsid d’eh kcub gnirps eht nevE
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.enola lla saw lrig roop eht
,regnad fo egdelwonk eht htiw lrig eht netsirhc dluow ecifircaS
.ecnarongi reh fo dlihc eht eveiler reverof dluow
,larutannu llems secalp namuH
tcaP elbatirahC ehT“
,htoot nori taerg sih htiw seert dellef ohw fao sselerac a saw eH .nwo reh llac sa
saw ehs sa gnitsurt dna sselesnefed
,tiaw ot gnilttes erofeb
mih devieced dah hctiw eht taht gnilkni on dah flow hsiloof
flesmih sediseb tserof eht ni srotaderp tsom wenk flow ehT
.ni saw ehs lirep eht dezilaer dna
.eromyna reh ot emoc ot deen on evah dluow rethguaddnarg eht ,tneps saw efil elbeef s’namow dlo eht nehW
.reveostahw ,raef on gniwohs
.deef ot dedeen yehT
.amsaim yldlrownu fo ksum ruos eht htiw gnignah ,krad saw tI
,yltnelis deretne eH
.taep dna tlam fo
.mrah on reh thguorb tros suoregnad tsom eht fo slamina taht
"!ereh thgir ,rehtomdnarg ruoy saw sa
,enod krow s'flow ehT
.detirehni won dah ehs taht stra krad fo
.detniat eb dluow ecneconni reh taht deirrow yleros
stsaeb ytfarc yb detalupinam ylisae era straeh tfoS
,reh rof thguard dlim a neeb t'ndah demusnoc rehtomdnarg eht hcihw werb eht roF
.seilf thguac wols eht dna
sa hcamots gnikrow ydaerla sih ot lufniap
deksir rethguaddnarg reh elihw
,snoitnetni doog s'lrig eht ot saw eh sa demraw tuB
,edisni sesoon gnitsiwt nerdlihc namuh rof yrrow htiW
,srae dekrep s’flow ruo no krow ot tnew ylgninnuc eugnot revlis reH
.demialcxe lrig eht
evil syawla tsum eno ,gnol evil oT
.eson sih deeh ot deliaf
.detnecs eb ot serutaerc sselesnefed rof retteb eht llA
.dedulcnoc elat reh sa dehgis sbuc s'hcrairtam ehT
.slautciv nwo reh rehtag ot kaew oot saw tsedle kcis s'lrig eht taht gninrael ,erob ehs doof eht tuoba deksa flow eht ,erutan nezarb reh yb desufnoC
.ecnarongi ni lufssilb
,derettum nortam flow eht
,redle eht delworg
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tsrif ta deltrats saw ehS
,dlihc gnirednaw a ssorca emac flow detas-llew ruo ,nus nmutua llihc a rednU
.meht derobrah taht stserof gniltsur eht dna
.kcots namuh fo tseitfarc eht saw tsedle siht dna
.dereffo rehtomdnarg eht ecifircas elbaronoh
,denruter lrig ehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
buc hcae erot dna
.gninrael saw ehs kciuq woh fo duorp os saw eH
.pus sbuc reh dehctaw ehs sa delims ehS
yawa evrac noos sa dluow ehs eert ylimaf reh no tolb a
,erutaerc elap eht llafeb dluoc taht lla rof dellews traeh tfos siH
,noitcetorp tuohtiw enola tuo erutnev ehs dluow niaga reveN
”looF detraeH tfoS A fo
.klis redips ekil sdooheslaf gninnips
.desimorp dah hctiw eht sa enola ylurt ton saw
stpircs dna snoitop eht nopu ylsselitip dezag
.enola tsedle s'buc eht gnidnif
ecalp ot ecalp morf erac tuohtiw gnitfird
,stlam gnitacixotni ,ytaep htiw gniknits reve htaerb
.yhw rednow wef ooT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,netae eb ot uoy rof retteb eht llA"
.licnuoc dna dneirf s'erutaerc yreve si noicipsus dna raef taht
.rotaderp yna raef ot hguone esiw saw ehs
,degarne reh gnignirb
".erutnevda na su lleT"
.lortnoc sih dnoyeb noitsuahxe yb derepmah saw tub ,traped ot dengied eH
.efil reh dne ot flow eht deggeb ehS .secifircas fo
ereht tuo sregnad sselitip eht ni deloohcs eb ot dedeen lrig ehT
.evah uoy seye gib tahW"
.saw eno siht sa noituac fo tfereb yllaicepse
,knird regnorts neve ot denrut namsdoow ehT
.seil dekciw wef a laecnoc ot hturt fo sratcen lufworros ,teews hguone deniatnoc
.nerdlihc namuh rof traeh tfos sih fo borht eht leef dluoc hctiw eht
.emalf morf deppils toos ekil reh tuoba delioc stnemtsev kcalB
,efil reh rof geb ot egru on dah ehs tuB
,desruc saw rehtomdnarg reh noihsaf emas eht ni demrahc saw lrig dekaolc-der eht taht saw mih morf droW
,ecafrus delknirw reh nO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.siht ekil enola derednaw ehs fi demusnoc eb ot erus saw ehS
.sesnes dellud sih ot buc flow sselriah a etiuq ton tub ,tsomla
.yrgnuh hguoht sa
#   .trap taht tegrof t’noD .ylleb lluf-oot a dnA
.plehw ynwarcs eht detseggus ",evol fo su lleT"
.nees eb ot serutaerc sselesnefed rof retteb eht llA  ".evah
.sgnivael dna sgnimoc s'rethguad enol sih rof nrecnoc yna tuohtiw
.swap sih htaeneb htrae enitsirp ylremrof eht fo snoitpurroc dlotnu htiw deluof saw ecalp siht tub
slaem thguac sevlow kciuq rof ,ylleb lluf sih etipsed kciuq saw eH
,sespoc dna sevorg hsul eht ni
.suoregnad era shcamots lluF ?reve yeht did
.thginot ton tub ,erahs ot modsiw erom dah ehS
,skcit citsidas s'emit ton dna
.aelp reh derepsihw ylluferac rehtomdnarg eht
.niap htiw gniyab selffuhs reh
,dnim sehctiw eht ni taht naht nis a esrow raF
knits gnitacixotni gnidaf eht ta eson reh gnilknirw
.depley eno suoitcnubmar reH  ".rehtona su lleT"
.sdoow krad eseht desrevart ehs emit yreve ytilativ teews nwo reh
.sbuc nwo sih hcaet ot nevirts dah flow eht hcihw snossel hsrah