.meht wonk nik riehT .tsal eht litnu tfig A  htaerb yrevE
nonniKcM ykS yb meop a
,nonniKcM ykS yb ”salleK fo htaeD ehT“ saw sihT      .gniK llac ew ohw
nrut ni smot dna
,moT dna neeuQ ,wodahs dna tleP"
,nozamA no elbaliava si
2 retrauq ni ecalp dn2 now ohw
floWcaM boR si sihT
tac tsetaerg eht ,salleK
O	  .dloH s'tseroF tA  degar taht semalf ot nilliK fo serohs eht morF
.deyarteb sevil enin dna ,devil sevil eniN
.nwo s'anoeL ot kcab wodahs
worrub dna tsen morf nerdlihc reh tfil oT
,”salleK fo htaeD ehT“
rebmemer lla teL .devol reverof ,denrocS  reveroF
.raey siht retal detcepxe si
".srats sseltnuoc ekil htrae siht llif ot nrob sI  luos sseldnuob hcae
,relevart wollef ruoy
,noows sneeuq riaf ekam sgnos ruoY  stsen rieht ni snettik ruo thgiled skcirt ruoY
yrots trohs riehT
,reh wonk swodahs eht klaw ohw stac lla roF
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
ykS wollof nac uoy ,noitamrofni erom roF
.oot reh wonk htraeh eht ta tser ohw esoht dna
”,etuC teeM“ ,yrots gnimocpu na dna
.llew os ni nrow evah swap ruoy sdaor eht klaW
,reyals ,revol ,reklatS  --ssentaerg rieht wonk lliw yeht ,meht gniwonk nI
.evol 'srehtoM rieht ni lauqE  eno sa lla
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.wodahs 'sicnyL ot denruteR  sevil eniN
yojne esaelP   .ykseulb no
.desopxe ,dnuorg eht nopu flesym nial roN  ,nik s'anoeL ot dewob I evah ecno toN
staC fo gniK ,salleK
'sicnyL  dael dna ,feirg morf traeh s'rehtom sih eerf oT  eman rieht ni tneps eb ot sevil enin htiw desselB
,nonniKcM ykS yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
”tsaC si thgiL yM erehW fo egdE ehT“
.erutuf eht fo sretirW s’drabbuH noR .L fo
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”,daeD gnilwoH eht fo thgiN“ s’lwoH notsruhT ni
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
stfig ’srehtom dna evol ’srehtom ruo derahs ohW  tser eht evoba eman eno gnis tsum I tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY