.t’ndluohs ebyam eh allef a rof nellaf s’namrevir tsrif eht t’nia uoY
.meht hguorht dereep dna kcen reh dnuora gnirts a no selcatceps fo riap a detfil
,gnihcaorppa erew yeht was renwo sti won retsaf gnivaw saw hcihw kced eht no feihcrekdnah eht ta bmuht a debbaj reedllik eht
.taht od ot yaw eno fo kniht dluoc eh
?taht ekil dnuos t’nod taht llet draeh hA ecalp ylnO
.mih fo noisrev wen eht no mialc on evah
.mih ediseb taes a ot deppolf dna llew sa derednerrus eh os
.stbed rieht fo latot eht ot lauqe
namrevir a nieb fo tniop elohw ehT
evac sih morf gnigreme timreh dam a ekil gniohce ,krab s’omluztiF ”,toN“ ”!nihton ro yaled yna esuac ot ’ninaem t’nia ylniatrec hA“
,sihpmeM tnaem ehs ,ylbamuserp ,hcihw yb
.ksam a niraew ,llat ,flow A
!mih ot ecnereffid yna ekam t’ndluohs tI
,floWcaM boR yb
,tesnus retfa thgin gnirewol eht ni
.yrgnuh dna ,sseltser ,krad
”.enim fo daeha ni semoc redrum a tuo ’niyrrac llits daed eb ot desoppus s’ohw nam eht kniht hA
”…htrof dna kcab niog tpek I os ereht mih ees ot krad oot erew’t dna
,dehctiwt pil siH
:flesmih ot tsuj saw ti gniredisnoc tcepxe thgim eno sa ylteiuq sa ton
,dias ti deen od uoy ,noonretfa emos ,thgin emos emoc ll’ereht tuB“
”.truh t’nia eh tub ,rednow on dna ,deveirg s’eH“
”gnitsalrevE sI gnoS ehT tuB
.rettam seod ti tuB
,dehcaer ylraE dna yadakceH niagrab revetahw ni dedulcni
”?yenoh yas uoy t’ndluow ,no sevom enoyreve fi denrecnoc lla rof tseB
”.lla retfa namrevir on eb ot tuo denrut I sseug t’nod I oS
,delley omluztiF ”draobratS“
.senots dehsilop ekil nus eht detcelfer sdap krad sih llit ,drawpu mlap ,sreh ni deppuc dnah sih dleh ehS
.namrevir a t’nia nehS uoy llet ydobon tel reven uoy t’nod tub
nihc sih htaenrednu morf eciov eht ffo tuc omluztiF
”,nihton ro tfarclleps yna od ot tuoba ton er’uoY“
.sufuR dna nevS ,seidob dekaos ,detsuahxe fo elip elttil txen eht ot no devom eh sa
”.niatpac ,yrassecen t’nia tub“ ,dehsulb nehS
”?eniw ekil setsat retaw eht dna ,ydnac kcor fo edam sniatnuom eht erA
.duht a htiw kced eht tih seenk s’niktiA ”?efas eh sI
.ylerus ,srepapswen ni saw tI
.erom yna yas ot derehtob eb t’ndluoc retto eht mih fo efil eht rof tub ,noitavresbo eht ot erom eb ot tnaem neeb evah thgim erehT
,ecivres hcruhc cisatsoirepa na ta hcram ecnarudne a ekil ,nohpitna gninord llud a otni denrut tI
”!draobratS“ ”!troP“ ”!troP“
.elbat a ffo sbmurc ekil yawa erohs eht hsurb ot fi sa gniw a devaw ehs
.revir eht tsuj saw ti
s’eelreggatS draeh“ ,nageb omluztiF ”,ellivsiuoL ni pu saw I nehW“
,ti detnuocca dlrow eht sa ,hpmuirt hcum yrev os ton spahreP
”!yawa ’niwots fo elbuort eht ay devas adluoW
”gnitsalrevE sI gnoS ehT tuB
.efil larutan s’ylraE fo tser eht rof
.eciov s’omluztiF morf deppird ytiludercnI
nO .emas eht eb eromreven lliw ,luos yrev ym ,traeh ym ,efil yM
”.niatpac ,ytilibissop tcnitsid A“
etartsigam eht si tniop
,mih sevol ohw etampihs eht ,niktiA neewteb nrot si eh tuB
”.rettam t’ndid ti em llet ydobon tel a’t’ndluow I dnA
meht dednuorrus won
.kcahskooc sih otni gnimrots erofeb
,suirebiT ,emit tsaL
.mih tnes revir eht hpmuirt revetahw htiw tnetnoc eb ot deraperp saw eh namrevir denosaes a sa tub
,dlrow sseldnal a ni enola
.meht fo yna ta pu kool ot animats eht dah dah nehS ecnis—
,tsap sih taht evorp dna
,elop gnidnal a pu thguac dna
”!riaf ylno s’ti yas“
.werc reh fo tser eht rof elttek eht no tup ,gnimuf llits ,kooc dlo na meht woleB
neewteb yltcaxe decnalab ylluferac yrev
”!si eh esruoc fo ,thgindooG s’enerI eht no terref eht s’eH
,os hguone detcarfer dna ekorb llits tnerruc ehT .gnihton toN
”!ris ,gnitsaw emit hguonE“
.eciov s’niatpac eht emac
,dniheb suirebiT nivael saw
,namrevir dlo na m’I nehw lleW
”?ysetruoc elttil a rof emit on tog t’nia uoy
?rettam ti dluohs yhw dnA
.neeb reve dah ti sA
.retaw eht ni gniliart teef rieht ,liar nrets eht no smra rieht ,rehtohcae tsniaga denael niktiA dna nehS
”.won gninword er’uoy naem hA .yob hsuH“
”,uoy ,ereh revo teg ,hcihw fo ’nikaepS“
.niatpac ot taob a tog llits I tub ,ma’am uoy htiw sgniod tsetal eht revo niog erusaelp a neeb s’ti ,lleW“
,riaffa ruoy fo enon s’taht ,em seirrac
”.yllaeR .n’pac ,onnud I“
.yrd ot enil eht ot sehtolc ffo-tsac ,dekaos gniggard ,kced eht dnuora deltsub ylraE
!loof eht suirebiT nieb a og tel t’nac eh snaem ti esuac
”.nehS s’eman ym ,lleW“
.seye ediw htiw niatpac sih ta kcab dekool
.tnemom a rof kced eht tfel seot sih os mih detfil
,ria eht ni niar llits saw erehT
htiw pu emac dna ,ees t’ndluoc nehS tekcop a ni dehcaer ,delkcuhc worc dlo eht nehT .tnemom a rof ,ylici ,seye dekcol yehT ”.neht ,no teg nac ew os eraf ruoy yap athguo uoy ekil sdnuoS“ ,dias omluztiF ”.em ot elbisnes smeeS“
yenom fo tnuoma na stnerap sih morf nelots d’eh
,doog saw hcihW .stbed rieht fo latot eht ot lauqe yenom fo tnuoma na stnerap sih morf nelots d’eh ,nosirp ot
”.esnecil on tog t’nod uoy tcaf a rof wonk I“
.mih dlot dah yadakceH .srM tahw tuoba yrrow ot eerf dnim sih tfel hcihW
,revir egral a ni taob llams a no ,neewteb nI
.dehcnilf omluztiF
”.boj eht hsinif ot yawyna kcab thgir emac eelreggatS ,thgin txen eht neht dnA
”.ereht ,drow ym ta em koot revir eht ebbem dnA
”!taob eht no erehwon mih llems t’naC“
.ytingid fo erutcip eht
.dias omluztiF ”.os tcepsus I“
.ruf s’retto eht otni ,ylivaeh denaorg terref ehT
”!emoclew YREV er’uoy ,yhW“ ”.ylraE ,uoy knahT“
”?epacse ,yrrauq lufwal ym
?teem sdne ekam ot tsum sdeen tahw gniod tsuj wodiw tsenoh na tuoba gniveileb trats thgim“
”.namrevir a tub gnihtyna neeb reven I
.dennalp d’yeht naht retsaf hcum yrev deirrac gnieb erew yeht dna
”?detniauqca teg ew llahs ,lleW“
,rehto eht won ,edis eno ot won ecaf sih denrut
,dias eh ”,klof s’erehT“
”,diarfa m’hA ,dlrow eht fo yaW“
,ti gnimmuh flesmih dnuof eH
,kced reh no gnidnats terref eht ffo seye sih nekat ecno reven dah
.dias omluztiF
”,hsuh dias hA“ .dias oriaC
,saep dna ecir decips htiw werc eht detneserp eh nehw oS
.kcahskooc eht fo llaw eht tsniaga ,kcab denael omluztiF
”sseug I ,thgirla taht draeh’Y“
,yawa gninnur yb taht delur dah etartsigam ehT
.teem ot klof rehto ,ot dnet ot ssenisub rehto tog hA dna ,ees ot emac I tahw nees hA won tub
ssensuoicsnoc tsol d’eh kniht t’ndid eH
,nihc eht yb nehS detfil dnah eerf reH
,yadakceH eiggaM .srM“
...sevieleb eh sa dniheb raf os eb ton yam tsap eht dnA
.edir a stnaw regnessap a snaem“
.rewohsnus eltneg a rednu meht eviver
!epip em dnif ot elihw a kooT“
.knalpgnag eht pu depmolc stoob gnidir nrow-llew reh sa dennirg ylraE ”!eb ll’I lleW“
”.delggums eb ot tnaw sa klof nilggums allef emos s’ereht draeh hA“
.retawhsid fo nisab a pmud ot tuo emoc dah ohw ,ylraE deksa nehS
”.erus m’hA ,demrahC
”.sseug I ,llac s’revir eht fo traP“
”.s’niatpac eht tub ssenisub s’ydobon t’nia ti dna
.draoba teg ot regae demees ehs ,saw siht reveohW .kcap suomrone na revo depard lwahs a dna
”.niatpaC ,taob ruoy no ecitsuj morf evitiguf a si erehT“
gnilkcac s’reedllik eht derongi nehS
.noitatluxe elitsoh fo lluf saw ,dehcaorppa thgindooG s’enerI eht sa ,tuohs s’gnilrats eht
.senicidem tnetap dna ,seidemer labreh ,scanamla fo royevrup
?ereht dlo worg ydobon seoD“
,rae reh dniheb erehwemos nioc s’niktiA dehsinav ehS ”!enif TSUJ
”.tserra rednu era uoy
.dias niatpac ehT
stnaw traeh ruoy erehw htob dloH
.liar nrets eht fo renroc eht ta ,seenk sih dnuora smra ,thgit pu delruc ,tas nehS
yltneg ,esolc mih dellup dna terref eht dnuora smra sih tup
,daetsni ,dias eh ”,n’pac eya ,hU“
.meht dehcuot yllautca eh fi gnihtemos kaerb d’eh deirrow fi sa ,detatiseh tub ,tuo smra ,meht fo htob revo denael eH
.devlovni troffe llams on saw ereht fi sa ,deniarts dna wols saw ti niaga ekops ehs nehW
,nosaes eht rof mraw elttil a neve ,thgin yrtlus a neeb d’tI
,klof ot ylteiuq sklat
,saw eiggaM revetahw ro ,namow relddep dlo yreve fI
.staobrevir ta gnikool trats ot ,tsael ta ,emos ot rucco dluow ti tuB
.kcab dennirg worc eht ”!eromineF ylraE“
yltneg debbob thgindooG s’enerI eht won dna
.detsetorp reedllik eht
.dnuohdoolb eht dniheb pu deltsub eh sa gnilrats eht derettum
,faol gnisir a otni tsif a ekil ,ti otni meht dehsup dah oihO deffuts-mrots ehT .rewols ,rediW
?slegna yb yawa koot erew tub deid reven ohw sgnik tneicna tog yehT
.gniredisnoc ,aet reh delriws eiggaM
.sevol eh ohw ,omluztiF niatpaC dna
,ekops eh erofeb ,tnemom gnol doog a rof ,esolc mih dleh suolehcA
.dias yllanif nehS ”,ksa athguo I gnihtemos si erehT“
,dluoc ehs nehw dnah s’nehS koohs dna kcap reh detsioh yadakceH eiggaM ”,yenoh ,ylbarimda
.niatpac eht detuohs ”draobratS“
,daeha revir eht ees ot elba eb ton ot emit dab a saw hcihw
.mih mialc ot tog
,rehtegot lla emit eht tup ot ,shtnom wef a n’erom tneps I ,lleH
”.yas d’hA ,elihw doog a gninword neeb uoY“
”?neht ,hcihw si eno hcihw
.rehtegot sretaw rieht dlew ot woh tuo dekrow srevir owt eht litnu
.redluohs eno revo depard ,ralloc eht yb ,taoc s’niatpac sih dleh omluztiF
,ta kcab ’nikool reven t’nia eh hcihw tsap sih ni sgniht tog t’nia namrevir on fo wonk t’nod I esuac ,yawa og tsap ruoy ni s’revetahw nikam tuoba onnud I ,woN .t’nac I tsaeL .dal ,teef sih rednu taob doog a tog s’eh ecno esle ydobon rof namrevir a ekatsim t’nac uoY
.egnahc eht dessim seye s’nehS ylkciuq os flesreh detcelloc yadakceH
.tew gnippird er’uoy ,daL“
.rellit eht morf ylpmil flesmih depard oriaC
,edis rehto eht no gnivird eb dluow hctaN dna nevS
,ecnaralCcaM suirebiT“
,stnap savnac ydruts
,nehS gnieb otni yawa gniwots yb pils eht nevig d’eh mohw ,owt esohT
.yrotirret aksarbeN ni ,hsulB troF yb pu noitavreser a morf klof eht flah n’erom yawa detirips eh draeh hA .enog
.srettam ekilhcus htiw niogysae s’eh tuB
,hctaN dna nehS ta deddon dna nioc eht koot omluztiF
?gnihtemos no nwod raeb did pihs eht fi od esoht dluow doog tahw ,gniog erew yeht deeps eht htiw hguoht ,sdrazah retawrednu tsniaga esnefed fo enil tsal a sa ,wob eht ta ,enac s’nam dnilb a ekil ,selop gnidnal eht htiw htrof dna kcab tpews sufuR dna eH
ydde sseltnerruc a ni
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.yap nac uoy taht si“
.regnad si doolb ruoY
.mih retfa eb dluow sffirehs fo riap eno eht tsuj naht eroM
,ees t’ndluoc nehS mlap sih no nrettap emos decart ehS
.dewo yeht saw ti revetahw fo latot mus eht ot lauqe tnuoma na meht morf nelots tceffe ni d’yob
.sgnits ti dna degnorw neeb I tub
,nosirp ot ylkeem gniog fo daetsni
,efas saw werc sih erus ekam oT
.neppah ot tnaem d’eh tahw eb llew sa thgim siht taht
”!niatpac ,ereh enod ton er’eW“
tahw s’tahT“ .delffab ,dias nehS
,edirp llams on htiw ylraE dekwauqs ”,eromineF ylraE desucca reve ydobon t’niA“
.erats ssalg kcalb s’dnuohdoolb eht tem eH
.eman ym dellac revir eht ,yob gnuoy a saw I nehw roF
.hpmuirt ni ,omluztiF muhamilaS suolehcA niatpaC doots wob reh ta dnA
.kcab s’niatpac eht no flesmih gnitroppus
t’nsaW ?evah ti dluohs
.ciffart revir rehto ees ton ot
sevooh nevolc sih tsel retaw ninnur ssorc t’nac eH .tey em thguac tnia eh tub ,em
”nehS ,erehwon og t’now I“ ”.esaelP .yatS“
.thgilnoom eht ni worbeye na dekcoc omluztiF
”,yenom yna evah yltcaz‘ t’nod I ,hO“
”,ksa uoy ohw sdnepeD“
”.mih t’nia sihT“ .dereviuq slwoj s’dnuoh ehT
.wets fo lwob a fo erutarepmet eht gnitset fi sa ,yllatnemirepxe
.gnihton dias dnuohdoolb ehT
llaw kcahskooc eht tsniaga pu tes d’ehs tnet llams eht yb tas eH
dnim reven tub yeksihw ni dennac neeb d’selppa eht ekil detsat—
naelc tsuj si saw’t reveohw gninrom eht ni neht
,kcab detuohs nehS ”!troP“
.dnuorg eht ni mih tuP
”!ton ro nam thgir eht ekil sllems eh rehtehw serac ohw ,shtnom rof mih retfa neeb ev’eW“
”.thgin lla gniht a draeh ro was reven ereht ymrA
.hcrop eht no gnixaler ollidamra na dna nooccar a htiw
reens yzal s’namrevir a dna tsehc erab a nehw ,lla retfa ,syad erew ereht tub
,elat llat a tsuj t’nia dna
,spuc nit fo hctulc eht dna elttek gnimaets yltneg eht ta derewolg omluztiF
,edir eht rof hcum os reve uoy knaht ,niatpac dnA“ .delims ehs ”,od hA“
.detarepooc uoy yas ot elba eb lliw I dna eugaelloc ym dna ,knalpgnag eht nwod tup si od deen uoy llA“
.revo eciwt mih gninmad yb
.enob nekorb a rof gnileef fi sa tsehc sih fo retnec eht nwod enil a decart sregnif owt neht
”?elas ref dnelb laiceps taht fo yna tog uoy ,oS“
.kaeb reh ffo deppils elims eht tnemom a retfa dna
,dias ehs ”,yenoh ,fo em edausrep ot tog uoy gniht ylnO“
”-dna ,ris ,revir eht gnidakcolb taobnug a evah eW !nur ot erehwon evah uoY“
gnoL sI msitpaB ehT“   yojne esaelP
tuohtiw thgilnus eht dna nihtiw aet eht tel ot neht dna
.niatpac ,dessorc tsal shtap ruo ecnis owt r’nossel a tnrael uoy sseug hA ,lleW“
?troP troP troP draobratS troP draobratS draobratS ro troP ro draobratS ti saw
,nik nwo ym yb yllaiceps ,evah uoy sa dab sa degnorw neeb reven I kniht t’nod I“
.eb ot neppah I reverehw ro ,kced ’o hctap a ro ,kcommah a erahs emoc ot emoclew er’uoy neht-“
.eciov sih detfil
,reddal eht nwod delwarc yllacitcarp niktiA
.kcab gnihca dna smra gninrub htiw rao sih dellup
”,oN“ ”-dna ffo yrd og uoy tuobwoH .enod mrah oN
”?oot em morf ti raeh ot tnaw uoY“
”.wenk I hsiW“ .derettum nehS
,guh ,yrd etiuq ton llits ,tew ssel a otni mih dellup niktiA
.yks etihw ylgnilzzad a ssorca deraems wobniar fo stnemgarf ,tsew eht oT
.nesool ot ecarbme tnalibuj s’niktiA rof emit emos nekat dah ti sa
…ekil ,deneppah ev’tsum gnihtemoS
,aes eht ni dnalsi na yas emos sI
,gniht doog a si emeht emas eht gnivah seirots sih lla taht dediced sah ohw
!ti fo enon morf yawa nitteg on t’nia ereht dna krow t’ndid ti snaem ti neht ,ti od t’nac I fi dna
.daeh sih koohs omluztiF nehw denworf eiggaM ”?nosaer yna rof dnA
!emas eht t’nia llems siH !mih t’nia“
.tuo erow oot s’esle enoyreve n’fi no elttek eht kcits ot enoemos s’ereht os
,tsehc s’omluztiF yb delffum saw eciov s’niktiA ”,ti od ll’I“
”!tey enod I ekil em ot kool t’nod ti hcihw ’,noitanitsed ruoy hcaer uoy nehw‘ dias uoy“
,yobloohcs a ekil dennirg revaeb eht ”,sn’pac rehtO
.naelc ylbaccepmi t’nerew kced eht fi sa seveels sih gnitsud ,teef sih ot flesmih dellup gnilratS eht
?erac ot evah eh did yhw oS
,2 fo 2 traP ,floWcaM boR yb
,tsehc s’niatpac eht morf daeh sih detfil nehS
,deffocs omluztiF ”,dnA“
.terref eht ot denrut retto eht nehT
nam gnorw eht rof hcraes elituf a ,tuo dnuof tsuj dah yeht sa ,ot eud deyaled staob no
”?htaed ot su klat ro aet ruo su evig annog uoy“
?ti dluow ,taht ees ylraE tel ot od t’ndluow tuB .yleritne nettogrof d’eH .deknilb omluztiF ”.drow sih peek t’nod eromineF ylraE dias eb ti tel reven dna ,erows I tub ,ti ekam d’eh kniht t’nid I
.gnas flesti revir eht demees ti llit
.eraf rieht diap s’regnessap a erofeb ffo ’nitsac otni klof klat ot gniyrT“
s’taobnug edakcolb eht won ,tsrif ’niog su tnaw yeht yas staob rehtO“ ,revo deppets niktiA ”!n’paC“ .dias omluztiF ”.taht ta ,did eh eb yaM“
.dehcterts dna teef sih ot kcab tog nehS emit eht yb ,revir eht revo snoitcelfer gnirettiks fo htap a derettacs dna ,lluf flah dna hgih saw noom ehT
er’yeht tuB ,thgiarts edam yaw rieht dnif d’yeht ,namrevir a erih tsuj d’yeht fI
”?doowtfird fo knuh dlo detsiwt ,uoy tey daed uoy t’niA“
er’uoy fi dnA( .ereht em rof nitiaw eb ll’namrevir elgnis yreve tuB
”.elat siht fo lacitpeks etim a er’uoy“
”.llet nac I sa raF“
”.taob siht no ecneralCcaM suirebiT eman eht yb ydobon t’niA“
,deneppah siht fi
.nwod tes sufuR dna resieW knalp eht ssorca demool dna rentrap sih tsap dehsup eh sa delworg dnuohdoolb eht ”,klat hguonE“
.kaeb sih ni sdrow demrala sih deppots noisserpxe s’retto eht tuB
”.gnirevihs er’uoy ,dal ,lleH“
,ippississiM eht htiw ecneulfnoc eht fo ,sseug d’eh ,selim ytfif nihtiw erew yehT
flesruoy deldnah uoY“
.uoy er’os dna ,won ereh s’eH“
.stbed rieht fo latot eht ot lauqe
ll’revir eht tub ,snedrub ruoy lla deirrac ev’I
.mih htiw dellac esle enoyna fi llet regnol on dluoc eH
,seenk sih ot terref eht teg ot htgnerts eht dah ylno
”,taht ekil krow t’nod ti ,yrros m’hA“
.dednal t’ndah brab sih deffim yltnerappa ,deppans gnilrats eht
”.mih erew ti niatrec ylthgir t’nerew morf ti draeh I esoht hguoht ,niaga tlik s’eh yaS
,dias terref eht ”,t’nia I“
?he ,dewonk ad’uoy dehsiw ahcteB
.rettam t’ndluow erofeb saw I revetahw neht“
,aibmuloC eht fo tsew
”.rettam t’ndluohs tI“
,gnipleh dnoces a evah dluoc oriaC os rellit eht no ,nehS elihw ,swen gnippaws—
s’thgindooG s’enerI ,levart ot deen hA emit yreve ekil smees ,sey hO“
,niatpac eht delley ”!troP“
:retaw eht saw ees ot saw ereht llA
.namreviR eht nehS ton ,ecneralCcaM suirebiT fo sriaffa eht s’tahT
.htiw retrab gnihtemos hctef ot ylbamuserp ,edisni deretnuas ohw ,ylraE yfsitas ot demees hcihW
.taob ym no toof tes uoy ecnis yad yreve ti devorp enod uoy ,llac eht draeh uoY“
,pu deffulf eson reh fo egdirb eht no srehtaef ehT
,ti ni nemwal eht lla dna
.nialpxe ot deirt nehS ”,ees ,oN“
,ksud dnuor‘ pu snrut tsuJ
,dloh eht morf pu gnimoc ylno saw eh hguoht
.retal ro renoos ,troper ot evah d’yeht mohw ot enoemos eb tsum ereht
.yawa tpews eb ot ton gniyrt saw terref eht dna doolf a ni knurt eert a saw retto eht ekil
”.pu nidniw er’yeht erehw si
”.woh ’niwonk ton namrevir a ,thgir t’niA
ekam ot
,yrgnuh ro tnelubrut dekool regnol on revir eht
.trap yciuj eht rof drawrof denael eiggaM ”.ton ebyaM .ebyaM“
.ylerus ,sdnasuoht fo sderdnuH
.nehS ot dettilf yletaidemmi seye s’yadakceH .srM
”?rellit eht ekat uoy nac ,oriaC
”.fles nwo ym ffo nitsac ekil leef I
.trela no yletaidemmi saw nehS taht hguone drawrof saw taht dnA
.suoires yrev ,dias yadakceH
”.yenoh ,uoy fo owt s’erehT“
.sreh fo htob ni dnah sih dleh ehS
.noitapicitna mirg ni ,elttil a tsuj
.ereht meht tfel niatpac ehT
.erew ti fI“ ”.mih erew ti fI“
”,etaredisnoc s’taht ,uoy knahT“
,tahnus daorb a ,kaeb a ees dluoc eh ereh morF
”.yenoh ,’ninword er’uoY“
.tnemelffab rettu htiw mih ta kcab dekool revaeb ehT
.gninetsil saw oriaC erus
.pihs eht no htolc yrd fo parcs elgnis a t’nsaw erehT
.eb ot esle erehwon tog I esoppus hA tub ,riS ,emit ruoy koot uoy ,lleW“
,nehS hcaer ot deganam tsomla
eviecnoc t’ndluoc nehS kcap reh ni tif dah ti woh dna—
”.wonk neve t’nod ylekil loof rooP
”.won rof ,t’now I nehT“
.thguac s’eh fi ,tsael ta ,esoon eht ’nicaf s’eh ti no nettirw srallod hguone s’ereht dna
.yldetniop deffins eiggaM
ti od annog saw I ,nwod og I nehw flesym dlot ’suj I“ ,dessefoc nehS
,detaeper dnuohdoolb eht ”,sihT“
.grubskciV dehcaer yeht nehw kcod eht no gnitiaw sffirehs erew erehT
!rehtien t’ndluow eh dna t’nsaw eh os ,ot droffa t’ndluoc eh esuaceb ,esraoh gnitteg t’nsaw eh ,on dna
”!nameltneg a nieb fo“
dias dna seye sih tem ehs ,ecnalg yrosruc a retfA
.rellit yvaeh eht no thgiew rieht decnalab nemrevir owt ,smra s’rehto eht ni eno eht
”!niagrab a ekam s’teL
”?ni gnittup ew era yhW“
.dluohs ti naht retsaf hcum resolc gnitteg saw knab eht tihs ha dna
.htaerb desufnoc a tuo tel nehS
.dellac neeb tsuj sah ffulb esohw relbmag a ekil ,dekrims ydal dlo eht
od ll’ynnep flah a
.rof ffo ’nittes klof fo draeh tsal yeht reverehw enog atsum yeht nimussa dna ,enog s’enoemos niraeh klof tsuj lla er’esoht dnim ym ot ,woN
gnoL sI msitpaB ehT“ fo
,dennirg eiggaM ”,niatpaC ,tcepsus hA“
.emit teews sti ekat nus eht tel dna kced eht no dekan yal tub od ot werc a rof gnihtoN
.ylmrif dias nehS
.deunitnoc eiggaM
.niaga dewolleb niatpac eht ”!draobratS“
,tohsrae ni saw nehS erawa yletuca saw omluztiF ”,tahT“
?nam gnorw eht eb ot wonk I tahw ’nitserra esoporp uoY“
.nwod deid gnirettum ehT
,I“ ?thgir ,gniwonk reh ni mrah on saw ereht ylbaborp neht raluger a saw ehs fI
”?ssap eno on tel t’now sdratsab uoy“
.dessap dah niar eht fi neve ,og
”.yletal ti rof llac hcum dah t’niA
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”?niod uoy er’tahW“
tlusni cibreca yreve koolrevo ot gnilliw yltcefrep saw nehS neht—
.kcahskooc s’ylraE fo tuo tsaef a hcus gnixaoc ni trap reh rof worc dlo eht ot delicnocer yleritne demees niatpac ehT ”.erom on dna
”,taht fo yna tuoba wonk t’nod I ,lleW“
.rentrap gnirettups sih fo sseldeeh ,thgindooG s’enerI eht ffo demrots dnuohdoolb ehT ”.em sepacse nam oN .rissoN“
”!omluztiF niatpaC“
,sdroldnal sih dna sreywal siH .tew teg
hplodnaR ni occabot fo sdaehsgoh htiw ffo deppot d’yeht—
,pihs eht gnittup saw eH
”.tibah ylnameltnegnu na si gnikoms taht ,yenoh ,llet ti draeh evah hA“
.devom meht fo rehtieN
.taorht reh deraelc
”.niaga neetxis fo lrig a ekil leef em sekaM ?taht ekil egaruoc ,eralced hA“
.llawmrots eht fo stnanmer naidisbo gnilbmurc eht decreip thgilnus fo stfahs ,tsae eht oT
ti yas ot s’ohW ?ecnereffid eht yas ot s’ohw neht dna
.taht rof enon flesruoy ’nisucca og t’noD“
,noitagilbo laicos etaidemmi reh fo deerF
.mih gnimialc dna revo gnisolc revir eht ro niar saw ecaf sih ni retaw eht fi erac ot derit ooT
,tfarclleps eb ’nog ylerab ylno s’tI“
,pu dekool noreh ehT
dekramer eiggaM erofeb ecnelis tnangerp a saw erehT
?eh t’ndid ,revir eht ot degnoleb eH
.moc.yrrufos.flowcam-bor ta yrteop dna
.reddal eht rof dedaeh dna
.nemwerc sih htob dnuora smra sih tup dluoc eh llit flesmih dnuora nehS degdun eH
.kcab sih no saw eh neht dna ,teef sih rednu edils kced kcils-niar eht tlef
.rehtohcae dnuor yaw flah meht detator
”.nur siht werc eht htiw no denioj ylno ,hu
.drawrof dednuos ti ,taht yb tnaem ehs revetahw dna
.derrits pitliat sih ylnO
.delffab saw nehS ”?lleW“
,loof a ekil ,efil elohw sih ni nrut doog a mih did tahw nam tsrif eht htiw
,tnemom gnol a rof daehrevo mraedis gnikoms a dleh
,nwo rieht fo eno tsniaga noitasucca eslaf a dna
,niaga yb emac eh sa ,dias ylraE ”,ees uoy woN“
,dennamnu saw rellit eht was
,rehtien ,taht od ot namrevir tsrif eht
”.eldniws a s’siht neht
.miws ot raef slegna eht hcihw ,nevaeh ni pu
”,namrevir a flesym ekam dluoc I fi denokcer I“ .ylmrif yrev tub
.miH ot ssorc tonnac yeht edis rehto eht no s’doG nehw dnA
,ylmirp ,kcab daeh reh detlit eiggaM
.rennid reporp a evres yllautca dna tuo lla og ot dah ylraE saw
”?taht eldnah ay’did woh ,ytisoiruc atuO“
,pu yawflah knalpgnag eht htiw hctaN dna nehS deppots
.emit driht a mlap sih otni peed dekool ehs sa ezeerb eht ni pu ti dleh dna ,pit regnif reh tew neht
,nosirp ot ylkeem gniog fo daetsni ,yawa gninnur yb taht delur dah etartsigam eht esuaceB
,dessefnoc suirebiT
”.yadakceH .srM ,esaelp uoy fi emit siht ecnavda nI
”?dnatsrednu uoy ,eerf rof siht od t’nac hA“
”.gnissap ni ,niatpaC eht dna ylraE wenk uoy ekil demeeS .ma’am on ,hU“
”.ot deen t’nod I ekil skool tub ,swen eht draeh uoy fi ksa ot ’nixif saw I“
.ma’am namrevir a m’I ,lleW“
,denrael reve gnivah tuohtiw wenk lla yeht gnos eht denioj
.foor eht fo gnahrevo eht rednu tsuj ,kcahskooc eht tsniaga delttes egaggul reh dah yadakceH .srM ecno ,deksa ylraE
”?thgir eb I dluow ’,niatpac taobrevir‘ dias I dna ,edart sih sseug ot em deksa’y n’fi
,nemrevir yrgna ynam yrev woh ot noitnetta s’eno werd yltbus hcihw
,tuoba wonk ot t’nia wal eht taob siht no deneppah sa gniht tsrif eht eb t’ndluow ti tcaf a rof wonk hA
ylkeem gniog fo daetsni ,yawa gninnur yb taht delur dah etartsigam ehT
”.yas d’I ,traeh eht fo srettam ni snoitacilpmoc emos tog uoy ,lleW“
”.’niredisnoc ,ega dlo n’ylekil erom dne a s’taht esoppuS
,derad eh sa ylwols sa ,denrut omluztiF ”,swen fo eceip riafnu lufrewop a s’tahT“
!?hctaw emoc annog werc eritne eht saW
.nosmirc suonimul dna diviv a
,pirg sih ni slepal dna ralloc s’gnilrats eht dah dnuohdoolb eht ,evom ffirehs eht was nehS erofeB  .stsirw s’nehS rof dehcaer eH
”,yawrednu er’ew ecno pu ’nihctac rof hguone emit eb ’nog
,teef sih ot kcab nehS pleh ot nwod dehcaer eH
,siht tuoba draeh dah
.nwonk llew saw ti neht
.srae s’nehS dekorts omluztiF
”!retaw eht ni em dehsup tsomla uoY“
,nrut doog siht uoy did ohw allef siht ,oS“
.deffins revaeb eht ”,ma I“
.srao rieht no retaw dekcab htob tarksum eht dna eh dna ,resieW htiw nosinu ni
snoisserpxe lufroloc yrev lareves htiw niatpac eht tfel dna ,demuf ylraE
”?esac ecneralCcaM eht tuoba draeh lla’Y“
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
”.ris gnuoy ,decudortni neeb ev’ew eveileb t’nod hA ,lleW“
.evil ot steg rehto eht neht ,seid eno eht fI“
.sredluohs s’nehS no dednal swap s’niktiA
,llew sa swerc rehto eht retaw eht ssorca dna ,werc siH
eciov sih tpek omluztiF
.niatpac eht saw mih revo gnidnats erugif eht taht ,erofereht ,elbaborp demeeS
.mih tsol yeht saw ti erehw yas d’yehT
,stbed rieht devlos adluow nosirp ot niog ecnis ,delur etartsigaM“
.lasopsid s’noreh eht ta kcen fo hcni yreve htiw foor eht fo egde eht revo dekans daeh s’oriaC
,rellit eht drawot kcab ,gninraw eht detaeper nehS ”!draobratS“
”.snoitalutargnoc tserecnis yM
”.nur eht ’o dne llit yap ym teg t’noD“
.ycneinel emos uoy teG
,suolehcA dezeeuqs nehS
.dias omluztiF ”?tahw lleW“
.evals yawanur a fo s’elat eht fi yltsom ,adanaC yas emoS
,ti ot pots a tup ot detnaw tsuj esle enoemos ro ,rof nimoc erew eelreggatS ohw erew ti fi onnud ,enoemos ,nillik tsal sih ta yas yehT
,rehtegot smlap sih deppalc ,wap s’nehS no taps ehS
.tsehc sih otno kcab yleruces ecaf s’namrevir rehto eht desserp dna
.’nivom
.ni won erew yeht eno ehT
.dias omluztiF ”.mrots a saw taht
.gnitset sti fo emit eht semoC
.dnal yldneirfnu htiw pu def sremraf roop tsuj ro srotbed ro sevals yawa ’nilaetS“
?yas ot eh saw ohw tub
,lleW“ ”!eiggaM ,niraews llitS“
.tniop siht ta ,oot elttil a ssenisub s’niktiA ebyam s’ti sseug I“
.neve ,esir dluoc nus eht erofeB .gnilbmarcs dna dehcnerd neeb dah yeht ylneddus neht
”.em revo yrrow lla’y edam I yrroS“
eht woh tsuj t’nsaw tI .teg
.werc eht derewsna ”draobratS“
”.ycavirp emos lla’y evig ll’I os ,nac I peels tahw teg dna ffo yrd og a-m’I ,won rof tuB
,eciov larhclupes sih otni gnipeerc lwoh suoiruf
.elop a pu dekcip omluztiF ”,me‘ htiw eugra annog t’niA“
,yenoh esruoc fo sey yhw dna
,dnah s’nehS ta dekool
?emas eht lla saw ti fi ,esaelp ,won ton tub ,retal ,taht tuoba leef ot owt ro gniht a evah d’eh wenk eH
”.neht ,ecneinevnoc ruoy ta mur fo guj a nitceps‘ eb
.keehc sih no dednal dah retaw dloc fo pord A
.tnaem dah ehs tahw ksa ot tnemom eraps a dnuof terref eht nehw mih ot derepsihw ehs
”.em revo emac tahw onnud I“ .dettimda nehS
.hguorht yaw eht lla namrevir a
lleW“
”,era uoY“ ”-ton m’I tuB“
.redluohs sih gnikahs enoemos tlef eH
,hsraM oriaC ,raey tsal uoy daer hA nehw ’nitcejbo uoy llacer t’nod hA
”,ma’am ,ti did I woh onnud I“
.taob ym no slanimirc ro syawawots ro sevitiguf on t’nia ereht ,oihO ni uoy dlot ydaerla I tub ,sreciffo ,draoba emoc ot emoclew n’erom er’uoY“
.derewsna omluztiF
.mih ediseb tauqs ot owt ro pets a koot neht ,niktiA rof redluohs sih revo dellac ,renroc eht denrut niatpac eht sa flesmih no ni rehtruf detcartnoc nehS ”!dal ,era’y erehT“
”.kcommah sih ’nirahs saw I nehw saw eh tsaeL
namrevir a flesmih ekam ot denimreted
,kooc tnellecxe na saw reedllik dlo eht ,mih htiw gnivil fo ytluciffid eht lla roF
.tnerruc eht otni kcab ffo delop dna pu ti dellup yeht dna
.mrah-fles fo sthguoht serudne yliraropmet
”.no yduts ot ’niyrt m’hA
.tnemom a rof ,gninthgil ekil ,deraeppa hteet prahs ylleurc fo hsalf ynit a tsuj dna
yenom fo tnuoma na stnerap sih morf nelots d’eh
.revir rehto eht deciton dna pu dekool nehS nehw saw hcihW
yas derad reven dna yawa mih worht dna pu mih esu klof tel ohw gniht elttil detnuts ,yrros a saw suirebiT
.dehgis omluztiF
.dennirg omluztiF ”,seod ti spahyaM“
.dekaeuqs eh ”?ma’am yltcaxe naem uoy’d woH“
.stbed rieht fo latot eht ot lauqe yenom fo tnuoma na stnerap sih morf nelots d’eh ,nosirp ot ylkeem gniog fo daetsni ,yawa gninnur yb taht delur dah etartsigam eht taht
t’nia eh ,llew ,niatpac sih rof traeh sih no owt ro tonk a tog ebyam s’nehS fi dnA
.kaorc ot deganam nehS
.msitpab gnol eht ogrednu uoY“
,rellit eht gniluah ,srao rieht gniluah ,derewsna werc eht ”!draobratS“
.deipucco erew smra sih sa ,daeh sih fo krej a htiw denokceb eH
”.dlohpu ot sdradnats lanoisseforp tog hA ,yenoH“ ”?tahw lleW“
.ekaw a fo yaw eht ni elttil tub dah ,tnerruc eht yb deirrac ,thgindooG s’enerI ehT
”.doom suoreneg a ni m’hA
.niatpac eht tsniaga deldduh
ll’I“
,wap s’terref eht fo noitanimaxe ni peed llits saw eiggaM
,rehtien ro ,htob ro ,hcihw srettam yltaerg ti esoppus t’nod hA ,’nitaluceps dnal yas emos draeh ,nilbmag yas emos draeH .stbed dab fo lufworrab elohw a pu nar yeht tuo snrut ,lleW .erots lareneg a snur ydal ,llim ruolf a tog dnabsuH
”,neht ,mih rof dooG“
.sredluohs sih dezeeuqs dna dennirg niktiA ”.d’wonk ew ,hO“
,kaeb reh ot regniferof reh thguorb ehS
,oot emirc taht rof ’ninnur eb ’nog s’eh dna
”,og ot eerf er’lla’y llA“
,retaw eht ssim rao sih tlef
.niar eht ni yawa dehsaw neeb d’yeht erofeb kced eht no dedracsid dah setampihs sih lla sehtolc eht dna namrevir ylenol a tub ecnetsixe ni tfel gnihton
revir eht erehw dnA .em yrrac
,niaga pu mlap s’nehS dellup eiggaM
,yltnerappa ,dewo srovaf eht fo enO
,doog dna llew lla saw ytirohtua ylniatpaC
hcum rof tnuoc t’ndid hcihw ,llet dluoc terref eht raf sa—
ecuas nisiar dna elppa dna ,mah dekab dna
.egassap reh syap ehs llit“
”.taob ym ffo lleh eht teG“
”!llacer I sa ,recnamelet yb su tcatnoc ot dlot erew uoY“
”!troP“ ”!troP“ ”!draobratS“
.detcidartnoc omluztiF
”?yaled eht s’tahW !mih no sffuc eht tup“ ,deppans gnilrats eht ”?lleW“
.wets-hsif-dna-stiucsib dna nocab-dna-stiucsib neewteb detanretla ylno eh nehw neve
.saw taht hcum woh wonk neve t’ndid eH
,deppots evah t’ndluow thgindooG s’enerI eht dna—
,kcab gnidloh allef eno tsael ta fo ytissecen eht swonk namrevir decneirepxe ylurt a“
.tsrif mih ot tog
,ksam a no tup
,erehwemos ereht tuo llits ,evitiguf laer eht gnittel yberehT
”,snilwa’N ni pu ylppus ew nehw ti evah ll’uoY“
?dluoc nehS naht retteb mih evol dluoc ohw enoemos evresed revaeb eht t’ndid dna—mih thguat dah niktiA ytnahs ehT
.depacse yob eht emit siht tuB“
.kcod eht fo dne eht ot dehcram gnilrats ehT
.hcuop htoclio na tuo dehsif ,kcap reh ot revo deltsub worc ehT
.dnah sih mialcer ot ydaer dna deveiler ,dias nehS
.sbos gnithgif ,meht fo htob pota ylivaeh devaeh niktiA
.mih devol ohw revaeb eht dna devol eh retto eht neewteb yal terref eht
.aes eht ot nwod llor ll’I
.gnirps yrd eht tuoba gninialpmoc pots dluow sremraf eht tsaeL
?yeht dah ,miws ot mih gnihcaet ot dnuora nettog yllaer reve d’ydoboN
hctac ot tuo s’lived eht lleW  .ippississiM eht
.erohsa kcab deppets eh sa ,detsugsid ,deyab eh
,erac llits t’ndluohs nehS dna
,gnidnal eht ta pu deit taob rehtona morf emac eciov yrgna na ”,yhw siht sI“
neht dna ,deracs saw I ,n’pac ,onnud I“ ,deplug revaeb eht ”…I“ ”?og uoy did erehw ,mih rof kool ot uoy ’lot I
,drawrof gninael erew dna
,knird ot ti morf taeh hguone nelots dah sdnah yraew rieht llit ,meht fo eerht eht neewteb puc toh eht ssap ot ygrene hguone tsuj dah eh won roF
,nosirp ot ylkeem gniog fo daetsni ,yawa gninnur yb taht delur dah etartsigam ehT
”.nrut ruoy ti sekam taht tuB“
aet fo puc s’eiggaM morf semulp gnimaets eht nrut ot elgna thgir eht ta tsuj saw ,tnemom a rof ,tesnus ehT
”?shtnom ynam sa ni eman sih ot redrum htxis eht ,tahw ,ekam d’tahT“
.retteb ssorca egassem eht tog
?ereht neeb eh dah gnol woH
.em ot rettam t’ndluohs ti esuac ,rettam t’ndluohs tI“
,niatpaC ,allef eno n’erom eb dluoc yeht a’tnuocca no evieleb t’nod hA seirots fo cipot eht nO“
,rellit eht no gniluah eb dluow oriaC dna niktiA dna
teg ll’revir eht dna revir eht no yats
.seot sih ot drib eht detfil dah
.rettam ton ti ekam t’nac I
evol ni llef dna tnew suirebiT !revir eht no ti edam reven adluoc suirebiT !oob
”!uoy evol I !uoy revo ’niyrrow em rof“
.yaw taht pu neeb
.detuop ylraE ”?lleW“
trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
”.ereh ,resolc ni teG“
,ton yhw dediced ,dennirg retto ehT
”.niatpac ,ssenisub dab a s’tI“
,omluztiF niatpaC .llew lleW“
,nehS eman eht gnikat
,enod dna dias d’eh eno tsal eht saw hcihw rebmemer neve t’ndluoc eh llit ti gniod neeb d’eh gnol woh fo kcart tsol allef a erehw dnik eht
!ecnereffid on ekam dluow hturt eht gnillet nevE
,haN ?sallef tnereffid ytnewt t’nia
”?pu nidniw klof eseht er’erehW“ .ni denetsil
.srats gnillaf ekil til erew spord eht dna gninihs saw nus eht tub
,kcab detuohs omluztiF ”,llacer I sA“
.ssenisub dab a n’esrow s’ti yas yehT“
,evaw gnidnats a dessorc ti sa hcrul thgindooG s’enerI eht tlef nehS ”-draobratS“
’nemwal htiw dloh ton od I namrevir yhtrowtsurt a sa esuaceb citehtapmys‘
”.tnaw ti evah dluow daeh ruoy erehw dna
,revir eht ni naht ria eht ni retaw ssel ylecracs saw ereht tnaem nwod gniremmah niar
ylbaredisnoc nesir d’flesmih revir eht taht osla saw ti
ll’I tuB ,lortnoc yam yeht dnal eht
.aet tnim ,yesessalom ,toh fo puc a deruop reedllik ehT
”.ecalp rieht ni nosirp ot nos rieht deredro
,knalpgnag eht gnidloh llits erew ohw
yawa ’ninnur yb neht
,taob eht ’o sedis nwod ’nimmiws detrats I
,taobesuoh a ,taob rehtona drawot skcod eht nwod edirts namow dlo eht dehctaw nehS dna omluztiF ”!ris ,niaga teem ew lliT
,tsuj I os dna ,dloh eht ni mih dnif t’ndluoc I
”?emit siht yrruh eht rof nosaer ralucitrap ynA
.retsloh sih otni kcab ti deppils neht
ruoh na revo neeb dah ti tub
”.aes ot ebyam ,sniatnuom eht otni pu ebyam ,deraeppasid eh ’niyas er’yehT
?miws ot em hcaet uoy naC“ ”?tahW“
,mih thguac d’yeht yas ot tog reven stnerap suorotiart ron etartsigam ron nemwal on
”!ylnameltnegnu saw ti dias tsuj hA ,enon uoy lles t’ndluow hA yas t’ndid hA“
!skoobkcehc rieht ni sllaftrohs elttil nialpxe ot sesucxe suorednals pu nikam trats thgim yeht ,yhW
sihpmeM dehcaer yeht emit eht yb lluf saw dloh ehT  .luos ym
.aet reh deppis eiggaM
”,pu wohs ot sneppah sa taob tsrif eht
.meht evigrof ot gniog reven ydaerla saw eH .niaga meht ees ot gniog reven ydaerla saw eH
”.won niyalp eb ’nog t’nia ew tub erofa niyalp neeb athgim eW“
tsuj si od attog s’eh lla ,epyt eht hguone kool yeht fi xof ro god ro etoyoc yna ,lleh ro ,flow yna oS
.taob eht dniheb retaw krad eht otni nwod derats eH
”?siht ekil eh si yhw ,n’paC“ ”’?ylraE ,uoy knaht‘
.grubskciV edam ew emit eht yb namrevir a eb d’eh em teb uoY“
,kcen s’retto eht tsniaga delffum
”!t’ndluohs ti tahw si ,deneppah a’t’ndluohs tI“ .dekaorc nehS
.noitcelfer nwo sih tuo ekam t’ndluoc nehS
,dias omluztiF ”,lleW“
.esac ni tsuj ,mih dniheb decnalg nehS
”.wonk d’I ,erew ereht fI
”,eb thgim ew kniht I ,hO“
.yrotirreT nogerO yas srehtO
,hguone derit saw nehS dna ,hguone mraw saw ydob sih dna ,thgit nehS dehctulc niktiA
,eeffoc fo pis a ekil ylluferac taews sih detsat
delworg ohw ,niatpac eht htiw ti tfel eH
”,yenoh ,etarobale ’nihtoN“
”.riaf dnuos t’nod“
.kcod eht fo noitapicitna ni
revir a s’ereht lleW
ot esle erehwyna dah retaw eht ekil
,dne eht ni ,revir eht tub ydobon dna
,eessenneT fo etats eht ni ecalp suolupop tsom eht
”.sseug I ,rehtegot tew lla er’ew tsaeL“
d’uoy ,tuo em kees ot ekil
ohw retcarahc a sedulcni yrots s'yadoT :gninraw tnetnoC
”?uoy fo tsal eht nees I t’nia ,egaggab ’lo uoy ,yadakceH eiggaM“
.ti denoitnem enoemos won ,skcod grubskciV eht dnuora gnitiaw staob fo dworc lausunu na eb ot mees did erehT
,seye s’wal eht ni ,revo eciwt tneconni sevlesmeht edam d’ohw sesaduj taocnrut etircopyh fo riap eht htiw od ot gnihtyna ees ot tnaw t’ndid eH .flesmih ees ot tnaw t’ndid eh
,foor kcahskooc reh potA
yrroS“ .ylivaeh gnihtaerb ,kcab deppets dna ,nap toh a saw ti ekil mlap s’nehS desaeler ehS
enot a ni ,omluztiF muhamilaS suolehcA niatpaC dias
dluoc ehs ytilibisiv fo hcni yreve dedeen thgindooG s’enerI ehT .elbissop sa drawrof raf sa seye sih peek ot daH .gninrut tuohtiw dluoc eh sa llew sa drawkcab dewolleb omluztiF ”!draobratS“  .flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
.ainrofilaC yas emoS“ .dias eiggaM
”-htiw DEGRAHC gnieb er’uoy tahw ylesicerp s’taht ,niatpac ,wonk OD uoY“
.llits ylluferac swap sih dna dessorc smra sih tpek nehS
’.noitcennoc lanosrep a tog I edulcnoc thgim enoyna taht hguone citehtapmys etiuq ton‘ dna
.tfel seno ylno eht erew niatpac eht dna eh ebyaM
”-elbaeerga s’niktiA dna
.retto eht dna mih neewteb doots retaw revir fo toof a naht sseL
.tsew tuo tresed eht ni ,hcruhc fo rennam emos yas srehtO
,edis eht ot despalloc nehS
.nehS si eman yM .ecneralCcaM on“
”.hguone eb athguo ’nihtyna neht ,ma’am ,aedi ruoy sawt n’fI“
?worromot nitrats ebyaM
.nehS rof thgiarts tnew eH
lleW“ ”.llew sa seid eno eht neht ,seid rehto eht fI
noitazilaer detaeper eht naht retteb tsael ta saw hcihw ,sthguoht sih rednu morf pu delbbub—
tem tsrif nehS woh saw taht dnA
.ereht llits saw kced eht tub ,kcab sih no neeb d’eh gnol woh wonk t’ndid eH
.tnerruc eht otni ylduorp dellor
”,yadakceH .srM ,draoba emocleW“
”.era yllaer uoy ohw ta kool a ’nikat ycnaf tsuj hA“ ,dehgual ehs
?meht ta siht gniworht ,ta gniyalp revir eht saw tahW
.tiaw annog er’yeht obmil ni os ,yloh dna hgih oot
,dettiuqca s’yeht won oS
.oihO ni neddih llits mih kniht dluow emos ebyaM .denword eh kniht dluow emos ebyaM
.meht kaerb t’ndluow revir eht tsurt dna
?tahW“
”.dne eht ni ,yresim tub ’nihton em thguorb ohw trop taht ro siht ni lerdnuocs taht ro siht fo smra eht ni
thgindooG s’enerI ehT
,uoy dlot ydaerla hA tahw wonk hA“
?morf emoc neve niar siht dah erehW
,gnilbmert eson ,tuoba tsac eH ”!esolc erehwoN
omluztiF ”!loag ni tup deyats d’I n’fi ffo retteb eb d’I dnA
”,siht ekil retawkcab a fo klofssenisub dednim-esolc eht esnesnon atros tahw llet nac ohw ,hO“
”?taht gniod skloF .langis lamrofnI“
,taob eht no enola flesmih dnif dna pu kool d’eh ebyaM
yas enoemos did ,ega dlo ym ni niraeh ym ’nisol ebyam ,taht draeh ton a’tsum I ,yrros m’I“
,neve ,dewo srovaf ni yap uoy tel ll’hA“
…hcihw ,dewols dah meht htaeneb revir ehT
?ylerus ,gnihton degnahc sihT .deid d’eh fi sa erus ,enod dna tsol dna revo ydaerla saw efil dlo siH
.draeh hA slesaew ,stfirhtdneps a elpuoC“ .ezorf nehS
”,ezigolopa reven t’noD“
,thgilnoom eht rednU
,lleW  ).ereht wollof retteb
”.lla’y ’o yna n’regnol thgindooG s’enerI eht no nippihs neeb I fo tnuocca no d’wonk I ,neht tuB
.pmuht eht dehsiler ylraelc ,kced eht fo elddim eht ni kcap dezisrevo reh tes ehS
hcaorppa s’thgindooG s’enerI eht ecnis ohw ,ffirehs dnuohdoolb ehT
?thgirla eh sI“
.ereh gnieb yb tsuj regnad ni niatpaC eht dna ,niktiA ,werc eht
.evom ot elba eb ot mees t’ndid eh tub ,kcab sih pu edils retaw dloc ekil gnihtemos tlef nehS dna
.rood kcahskooc eht fo tuo ylitnuaj deppop ylraE ”,taht tuob‘
”.enif lanimon a ylno ecaf ot flesruoy uoy rof egnarra nac ew tsurt I tub ,deirt eb lliw werc ruoy dna ,esruoc fo ,detacsifnoc eb lliw taob ruoY
”,dratsab gums uoy ylraE“
.tuo gnar tohs A -ot neve ebyam dna ,maets dliub ot ,flesti no deef ot nageb ,taob ot taob morf daerps ,gnirettum yrgna eht taht hguonE
.esolc mih dellup dna tsirw eht yb niktiA debbarg
.llew sa omluztiF tsniaga gnispalloc rof delttes dna
.ekil tlef yrd gnieb tahw rebmemer t’ndluoc eh dna
.evom ot derit ooT
.rentrap sih dnuora deppets gnilrats eht ”,esnesnon rof hO“
,revir sselerohs a no enola
”,ynnep flah a evig ll’I“
.rellit eht ekat nehS n’uoy ,niktiA“
.sregnif owt neewteb nioc rallod a
”!htuom sih ni devohs ragic a tog t’nod staobmaets ycnaf meht ’o eno yna no tiwtin ycnaf a t’nia ,eiggaM ,tor s’tahT“ .tahnus reh gnitsujda ,derewsna worc ehT
,xelfer yb ylerup ,nehS
”?dal ,su htiw llits uoY“
,retawniar fo xulfni eht htiw
?ksam a ni flow a eb ot desoppus s’ti ,kooL“
”?miws ot woh wonk t’nod ohw“
elbaliava tnerruc tsenaelc eht rof eporg tub od ot gnihton saw ereht esuaceb
dekaos sa tsuj saw ruf s’nehS won dna ffo lla meht llup saw od ot gniht ylno eht dna dnuob dna gnulc yeht llit sehtolc s’werc eht dekaos dah niaR
,deilper omluztiF ”,eno eht t’nerew I“
.stbed rieht fo latot eht ot lauqe yenom fo tnuoma na stnerap sih morf nelots d’eh
.ciffart revir gnissap eht ta feihcrekdnah knip a gnivaw ,kcod eht fo dne eht ta gnidnats erugif a saw ereht tub