,deirt dah narocroC tsuguA fi ssem a fo hcum neeb evah t’ndluoc tI
,hguoht ,redlof knuJ taht gnieeS
.emit siht flesym pleh t’ndluoc I
.daer uoy sa taht tuoba drah yrev kniht t’ndid uoy epoh I
.neeb dah enohp sih sa tsuj ,drowssap oN
.t’nevah I emussa ot thgir erew uoy tub ,ylkciuq os ti dehsinif uoy desirprus eb t’ndluohs I
,ekil eht dna ,maps ro stnemesitrevda ,sllib fo snoitacifiton
narocroC tsuguA hguoht sa
.noitagitsevni yna fo trap etirovaf tsael sih syawla saw ,thguoht eh ,sihT
siht tuoba neve ro ,tsuguA tuoba nrael ot artxe gnihton saw ereht
—neve ,enod eb ot dedeen eH
.koob eht dekil uoy raeh ot dalG  ]tcejbuS oN[ :er
,llet ylbaborp nac uoy
ni saw eh tnemtrapa yrev eht fo
.redlof knuj eht ni ylisae dna
,moor elpmis rehtar a saw tI .moorhtab eht
,eno ton derevocsid eh
,seye s’narocroC tsuguA hguorht dlrow eht nees dah eH
.krowemoh gniod eb ot tnaem saw eh nehw
,rac sih ot dluoc eh sa ylidaets sa deklaw ,pu gnuh ecnaL
,nehT .rewsna on htiw
,etad laer tsrif sih no detisiv eh htoob otohp eht morf
.niaga uoy morf raeh ot doog si tI
oN[  .lla ti detrats taht egassem eht dna ,xobtuo eht ni
.em rof gnirettalf t’nsi txetnoc eht fi neve
,krow sih hsinif ot dedeen eh ,erom neve ,teY
,nrubuA ni emoh ylimaf a fo serutcip was reyD ecnaL
trofmoc eht laever ot ,ylerus tub ylwols ,yawa detlem
rehtona retfa eno gnihsinif
,ecnaL neve taht woleb ylitsah os delwarcs seton erew ereht tey
.no ecsinimer dluoc yeht taht
yppahnu rehtar a dewodahserof ti taht dna ,tahT
,sraey tnecer ni ylerar erom ,niaga
,potksed sih no smargorp on dah narocroC tsuguA
.ti fo edistuo esoht sa deirav sa tuoba erew erneg rediw eht nihtiw stseretni sih taht
,swalf sih fo etips ni
raf os narocroC tsuguA tuoba denrael dah eh gnihtyreve esuaceb
.seiromem nwo sih sa raelc sa snoisiv esoht fo emos
,lufrednow si boj ehT
.seno dab eht daer ot esohc syawla
emos em dnes ot woh nrael ot esimorp uoy fi
gniretne reve emit tsrif sih ekil tsuj ,esnesnon slebal eht
.ereh eb llits d’eh ebyaM
.emoh eht fo tuo deklaw dna
gnitseretni yrev dednuos ti tub ,slevon eht tuoba yllausu er’uoy wonk I
,llac enohp eht edam dah
,ekam ot dedeen eh llac eht edam dna
ecnaL thguorb taht tros eht saw tI
narocroC tsuguA neewteb ereht saw ron ,narocroC tsuguA dna ’ycnegremE‘
,eye sih morf raet a gnipiW
rettiwT no meht wollof ro
.yawyna ,ffo emit deredro neeb evah d’eh
,enimre eht depahs dah ohw dna tahw ot sa
,taerg gnihtemos fo
.dah eh naht emit erom raf
.stcatnoc sih ni ydaerla ton rebmun a morf llac a derewsna ecno reven eh dna
.nrubuA fo sbrubus eht ni tuo
,eurt eb t’ndluoc ylniatrec taht taht gniwonK
.3102 ni ,hcus eno saw enohp eht no llac tseilrae ehT
,der a htiw neercs a sa raf sa tog ylno gniht ykcolb ,tneicna eht sa
yrotsih llac ehT
,enod saw krow sih nehW
swen htiw saw ti ,semitemoS
,)tnemom eht ni pleh ton did yletulosba hcihw ,kniht I ,enimre na(
.dia edistuo on htiw
,llac enohp ylkeew a deludehcs dna
.toidi na ekil gnileef naht
emit fo doirep eht ot nward flesmih dnuof ecnaL
,devil eh yrots lufituaeb eht saw
.llew era accebeR dna anilegnA epoh I
,potpal eht desolc ylluferac lacarac eht
,liaf tuohtiw ,keew yreve tuB
,deirub narocroC tsuguA dna deifiton uaessuoR
,noos nrubuA fo serutcip emos uoy dnes ll’I
.oot ,gninnigeb eht fo hguone dootsrednu eh thguoht eh
.oga raey a liame eht detaerc ylno
,egap eht dedlof eH
flesmih nees evah thgim eh woh
.meht ni devil dah ohw
tnaem taht rebmun a esoohc ot enoemos rof erar ylbidercni saw ti
—rof gnikool neeb d’eh rewsna eht reyD ecnaL evag
,neht neve enog lla ,elpoep eht dna
semit eerht ,eciwt ,ecno
,serutcip dah llits eh dnA
.elttil a enoz ym otni
,emit tsrif eht rof mih was elpoep rehto sa flesmih was eH
,tsuguA raeD yM  2 fo
,niaga ecno ,fo ,kcab shtnom gniog
.liame taht ssecca ot
.rehtegot htuoy rieht fo hcum os tneps dah ohw esoht fo ytirailimaf dna
.seitnewt ruo ni ereh emac ew fi sevlesruo ro ecalp eht deyortsed rehtie evah d’ew tub ,tisiv ot detnaw syawla ew wonk I
ti decneirepxe evah dluoc ohw enoyna dna ,dlrow rieht otni uoy gnitropsnart fo yaw a dah
.lla ta segassem lanosrep on htiw
narocroC tsuguA .dluow reyD ecnaL
rebmemer I gnihtemos rof leurc oot leef sdrow rehto yna tub
,emoh sih ni ecafrus yreve tsom no
neewteb taht retfa noitacinummoc erom on saw ereht dna
.ycnegremE‘ ,tsal eht ,dnA .leinahtaN delebal saw
–moor gnivil eht ni edistuo dleh eno lacisyhp eht ot ralimis ylbidercni saw xobni siH
.knab a eno dna ,rotcoD
,cireneg eht saw dah eh llA
,deneppah dah taht gnitseretni tsuj spahrep ro ,elbirret ro
,sesod tuo gnitirw ekorts etarebiled ,wols eht ot eud ,dlob nar kni ehT
rood eht fo edisni eht ot depat repap wolley thgirb A
eb dluoc eh sa tpar sa
,eivom eht ni deneppah taht gnihtyna rebmemer t’nod I
.detnaw yeht taht yaw lacinilc eht ni
.tnatropmi gnihtemos derevocsid d’eh tsael ta
,dessap ecnis gnol dah
.sgnilbis redlo sih morf gnisaet eht saw eH
potpal a fo kcirb llams a
,detnemucod ssik tsrif emas taht dna
ti ees dluoc eh esuaceb ,thguoht eh
”narocroC tsuguA fo htaeD dna efiL ehT“
,noitacidem nwo sih ,tnemtrapa sih ni t’nerew sgniht eseht elihW
,semit ynam srebmun enohp rof tenretni eht hcraes ot dah dah ecnaL
.tsurt dluoc eh ohw nosrep eno eht dnuof eh erehw
lacarac eht dlot kool kciuq a dna
devil eh erofeb gnol semit tuoba
gnirraj os ecneirepxe na dah reven d’eh
.moc.liamvres@noyltn
,digir saw tpircs ehT
.koob eht dehsinif ydaerla ev’I
,seihpargoib otni debrosba neeb dah narocroC tsuguA hcihw ni
,)eveileb nac uoy fi rednetrab a sa(
.hturt eht dnif ot neeb dah reve eh sa denimreted sa ,moorhtab eht tfel ecnaL ,os ,dna
.ecitsuj lanimirc ni devlovni eb ot detnaw eh gnikniht ni tnits trohs sih morf erehwemos yawa dehsats skoobtxet dah llits eh tub
.noitazilaer sih htiw ylneddus os nwod hsarc mih dnuora dlrow eht tlef reven dah dna
,noyL ylbamuserp ,leinahtaN A .dael
.tros yna fo drazah a
,gnitirwdnah s’narocroC tsuguA gnidaer ni won decitcarp
,tnemtrapa eht deretne d’eh ecnis dessap dah sruoH
s’tsuguA morf retirw dnoces eht fo
.emit tsol fo sraey gninnaps evol A
,steknalb delip eht rednu morf tuo gnikeep
,srettel gnidnes naht retsaf si em gniliame
,elzzup eht fo eceip lanif eht gnidnif
.ti ta doog eb d’uoy eveileb nac I
.eciton s’tnemom a ta ydaer saw potpal sih
.flesmih emit taht fo hcum hguorht devil dah enimre eht taht wenk eh dna
.26 .enimrE .niaga narocroC tsuguA htiw
,gnitirw sti nopu neeb evah thgim retirw eht deilpmi tpircstsop eht sa ffits sa ylniatrec
,hguoht ,ni gniklaw morf flesym peek ot dah ev’I
,gnirob a saw tI .thgit dna ,taen
,htiw tcatnoc dah narocroC tsuguA srotcod ynam woh tsuj gniwonk ni ,revewoH
evah thgim ecneirepxe nwo sih taht gniwonk
noyL leinahtaN dna narocroC tsuguA
.ti wonk ot dedeen eh dna ,erehwemos detsixe narocroC tsuguA rof
.gniod saw eh tahw ,saw eh erehw nettogrof dah eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.egniwt suovren taht htaenrednu ,koob rehto eht ni tsrif eht debbud dah ecnaL mohw sa retirw emas yrev eht
,mih fo tnorf ni thgir
.efil sih ni ekil neeb evah thgim enimre eht tahw tuoba dluoc eh tahw gninrael
,esirprus s’ecnaL ot ,dnA
,enimre eht enigami ylisae ot ecnaL dewolla egap a nrut ot swalc sih pat dluow eh erehw stned llams eht dna swap sih ni esolc ti tpek evah thgim tsuguA erehw
.hguoht ,ereh llits htob er’eW
,dnim s’reyD ecnaL ni ecalp ekat ot gninnigeb saw erutcip detelpmoc A
,kool ot mih rof ecalp erom eno ylno saw erehT
,yromem s’narocroC tsuguA ot tlusni na eb dluow erutcip lluf eht naht ssel gnihtyna htiw gninruteR
.wonk I nosrep tsegnorts eht er’uoY
,resworb tenretni dellatsnierp
”—os ,won thgir ni ton m’I .noyL anilegnA fo ecnediser eht dehcaer ev’uoY“
.potpal eht naht oserom ylniatrec htob dna
.moordeb eht tfel dna
,tcepser emas eht
.txen eht dna ,txen eht dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,derahs yeht taht ssik tsrif eht saw eH
.dootsrednu eb ot tnaem reven erew taht
,lluf saw xobliam ehT
.etaf emas eht ot demood era lla ew yhw saw
,krow sih saw eH .tsal eht dna
.hguoht ,esuoh a gnivael erofeb gniht a hcus gniod ton fo ycilop a edam eH
.niaga ffo kcab gnittuhs erofeb ti ssorca gnihsalf yrettab ytpme
.daol ot koot ti emit eht no nwod tuc ,ylerus ,dna
,notnevaH morf yawa raf s’tI
.drow rof drow tnemugra eht fo trap ruoy rebmemer llits ylbaborp dluoc I tub ,eman eht rebmemer neve t’nod I dna
,ti htiw emac taht htmraw eht dna
tuo hcnarb ot uoy teg ot
tnemtrapa llams eht ni syawla ,narocroC tsuguA laer eht wonk ot nettog evah dluoc eh dehsiw eH
.emit tuoba denrecnoc ylralucitrap t’nsaw narocroC tsuguA ,ebyam ,rO
,tenibac enicidem eht delaever nepo ti gniyrP
.erom saw eh ,hguoht ,nooS
.redaere eht htiw swap sih ni enohp eht decalper ylkciuq eh os ,htiw yppah yrev saw eh eno t’nsaw ti hguoht
,tsrif tupni ot tahw ediced neve dluoc eh erofeb
flesmih ta kool evitalpmetnoc ,gnol tsal enO
.nrubuA ni devil dah ohw
,htaed sih litnu ,raey a revo roF
,raf ekat dluow ti taht wenk eh tub
,oga sraey wef a gnissap siroB htiW
,detnaw eh erehw tuB
,ega fo gnimoc ,ysatnaf
.efil wen elohw a devil d’eh taht tlef ecnaL tub
erusne ot deen ot tros eht ton saw enimre eht taht ecnaL dlot evah dluohs
,gnorw sleef tnemugra na ti llac oT(
eno siht taht wenk eh tuB
.ti fo tnorf ni tsuj rehto hcae morf ssorca gnittis knis dna teliot a dna ,nepo nward sniatruc rewohs
’.tnatropmI‘ delebal tsuj
,deid dah narocroC tsuguA erehw dna nehw wenk ecnaL
.derac syawla eh tuB
.raey fo emit siht
.thgirla eb d’uoy gnileef a dah syawla I tuB
,noitcif ecneics ,lacirotsiH
,ecnaL .semit ynam
,tub ,did I fi neppah dluow siht wenk I esuaceb
,flesmih esopmoc ot tnemom a koot reyD ecnaL
.nem owt eht rof gnidne
,feiler s’ecnaL ot ,enO
.knis eht evoba rorrim eht ot thgir tes eh ,os ,dna ,saedi wen on reyD ecnaL evag dnuora kool kciuq a dna
.derac ohw eno ylno eht
.boj wen a tog tsuguA
.selif ro sredlof on
.0202 ylrae ni degnahc nrettap eht ,hguoht ,yltpurbA
,dloheb dna ol ,tuB
srewsna rof dehcraes reyD ecnaL ,emit tsaL
?ycavirp fo yaw eht ni deen emoh sih tfel reve yldrah ohw nam a dluow tahW
.eivom orehrepus eno taht htiw ,edam nodnarB ekatsim emas eht ekam t’now I
,noitces sesaeleR weN eht ni siht dnuof I
detcennocsid neeb dah rebmun eh taht noitacifiton a dna
.mih dniheb efil elohw sih ees ot sa
.delliw-gnorts ylbidercnI
,tcefrep ylraen os hteeT
.seirots fo stros lla raeh ot teg I dna
lufituaeb saw nrubuA draeh d’eH
,srieht fo ffo gniog srehto fo htamretfa eht gniees retfa deen thgim eh dediced eh tahw
.tfel seno tsal eht er’ew sseug I
,semitemos ,taht wenk eh teY
.yna tsuj ton dna
,setaicossa nwonk ro sevitaler gnivil on ,elgniS
.ti htiw og ot regrahc eht dna
,kcuts syek eht dna
,detneserper ti lla fo luftcepser
,edisa doots eh deb yrev eht ni ylbatrofmoc dial
.tnemom taht ta nwo sih fo ssol a gnicneirepxe saw reyD ecnaL
.rettel eht rof uoy knahT
.efil ot emoc thgim ti taht
.tif was yeht yaw revetahw ni tser ot dial eb dluoc eh taht dna
dnuof eh nehw dlrow eht ni htiaf s’reyD ecnaL derotser tI
.gnissap sih fo wonk —ot deen ro —ot tnaw thgim ohw tuoba dna
,tniop eno ta ,d’eh esuaceb
,ecivres ni llits saw erus neeb t’ndah ecnaL eno
.noisseforp s’ecnaL ni doog reven saw ,lanosrep sgniht gnikam
htaeD dna efiL ehT“   yojne esaelP
.derebmemer eb dluow narocroC tsuguA woh si tahT
,niahc eht ni liame txen eht gnimmiks dna gnikcilc morf flesmih pots t’ndluoc eh tuB
.gnidne yppahnu s’yrots eht fo etips ni dna
.reh tem reven dah eh hguoht neve
.segap sti nihtiw ,leinahtaN
,rednes emas eht morf saw ti edisni egassem yrevE
,selif sih dah eh dnA
.uoy ot tuo gnihcaer rof seigolopa yM
.liamvres@noyltn si liame ym os
narocroC tsuguA tuoba thguoht evah dluohs eh taht dezilaer ecnaL
,krow dna ylimaf htiw
,oot ,troffe elttil yrev koot raf taht kcab gnillorcS
.yrt ton dluow eh yrots a t’nsaw ereht demees tI
,gnab a dedeen ,detcepxe
,eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo ecnaL ot deraeppa gnihtemos
.lufetarg neeb evah dluow
.ylerar erom neve meht edam eh dna ,sraey wef tsap eht rof ton tsael ta
,meht ot tnatropmi saw tahw fo
.htuoy sih ni ti derebmemer eh sa nwot eht dna
,tem reven dah eh nam daed a esongaid ot tnaw t’ndid eH
.reyD ecnaL deman saw taht
,noitacidem DHDA neve dna
enohp s’narocroC tsuguA ot nruter A
,wor pot eht evoba pu gnikop tsuj
.ypoc ’seviL ruO ot taerhT ehT‘
.hguoht ,tnemom a rof ti terger t’ndid ecnaL
.tnenitnoc a flah dna sedaced
.sraey wef tsap eht revo dneirf a desu evah dluoc eh ebyam ,thguoht ecnaL
.esucxe na lla siht evig ot
,saw esuoh sih fo tser eht fo hcum sa ,tsuJ
.nisuoc a ro gnilbis a eb ,llet dluoc ecnaL sa raf sa ,neve dluoc taht gnihton ,selcnU on ,stnuA oN .daD ro ,moM delebal tcatnoc oN
emit tsrif eht saw eH
,leinahtaN  ]tcejbuS
,mih ot ngierof yleritne erew selttob egnaro llams esoht tub
.liam eht ni gniviecer neeb dah narocroC tsuguA segassem fo tros emas eht
fo trap lanif dna
yrots a dah narocroC tsuguA
,snoitseuq derewsnanu dah llits eh esuaceb
.od ot mih dlot esle enoyreve tahw
,dna ,taht tsuj saw gninnigeb eht dna
gninnaps ,evol erup A .evol fo
,liaf tuohtiw ,keew yreve ,dna
.hguoht ,yrots tnereffid a dlot
.pu kcip dluow narocroC tsuguA
ylkciuq emas eht hcum fo htrow sraey lareves dnuof ecnaL
delebal erew stcatnoc eht fo neveS
,flow naicisum a dna
.detcepxe sa tsuj
,revetahw ro ,ti etanod ro ,yawa koob eht worht nac uoY
emoh ylimaf llams a fo rebmun eht
.em evig uoy htgnerts eht fo esuaceb ylno s’ti ,gnorts m’I fI
.sessalg dednuor ,egral oot spahrep ,egraL
.ytpme morf raf saw elttob hcae dna
wor mottob sih no htoot gnikool prahs eno ,eno tub lla ;thgiarts dna etihw
.elttil taht tsuj htiw dnif ot elba eb thgim uoy sgniht etavirp dna elbirret eht fo lla denrael dna
.enod tsomla saw eh taht ecnaL dlot
,daer reven eh skoob tuoba daer eH
tsap gnol emit a derebmemer ro
tcepser eht tlef eH
.denifed eb dluow narocroC tsuguA woh si tahT
,flesmih narocroC tsuguA neve dna
sgniht erew erehT
?ew t’ndid ,hguoht ,sevlesruo gniyortsed ta enif tsuj did ew sseug I
,dehcatta gnitteG
”narocroC tsuguA fo htaeD dna efiL ehT“
,dna ,seirots lufrednow ynam os dah evah d’eH
,hguoht ,semit wef a ereht tuo nettog evah I
,ecnatsni ralucitrap siht ni ,tey dna ,gnihton
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,nwod tas eh dna ,sgel owt nwo sih yb retupmoc taht fo tnorf ni deggard
;gniht a degnahc evah ton thgim ti taht denrael ecnaL ,tuB
.nruter syawla dluow yeht tub
.no denrut ti tub ,elbanigami yaw yreve ni degdums dna dehctarcs saw neercs eht dna
,desu dah leinahtaN ecivres emas yrev eht
ta ti t’nsaw taht tub
,dednemmocer dah rehto eht
delaever elbat edisdeb eht ot reward eht nehw yawa thgir dedrawer saw dna
,flesmih fo etips ni gnilims flesmih dnuof ecnaL
.eno siht naht drawkwa erom neve ,tcaf ni ,erew 3 hguorht 1 stfarD .S.P leinahtaN ,tseb eht llA
”narocroC tsuguA fo
.setadpu erom rof
.evah thgim ylniatrec eh tub
.krow ta syawla saw eignA erehw emit a ta
nam eht tsuj otni werg
,hctam ot serutcip htiw ,egelloc neht dna
.noitartsurf peed a esora ti
.hcum yrev ereht gnikrow em dekil evah dluow eignA erus ton m’I tub
srettel wef tsrif esoht ni ytidigir ynA
,niaga ,dnA .elttil yrev
,netsil thgim ytitne revetahw ot gniyarp
dnim s’tsuguA otni teg ot redrah gniyrt neeb dah ecnaL esuaceb tsuj saw ti
,emit eht dnif ot tluciffid yrev s’tI
enot laid elpmis A
,gnidaer sih ni uaessuoR morf txet a derongi dah eH
,tfig yadhtrib ruoy eb nac koob ehT
.tsrif seye s’ecnaL thguac
.evisavni oot spahrep ,lanosrep tlef gniod saw eh gnihtyrevE
tsniaga ,ti otni tup eh erac dna evol eht dna
,uaessuoR ot troper ot hcum evah t’ndid eH .ffo evord dna
.oot ,ti dehsinif ev’uoy taht wonk dna uoy morf kcab draeh ev’I litnu ,tey gnihtyna yas t’now I tub
.gnikcehc rehtob ot deen eht leef t’ndid tub
.etsat doog yrev sah erotskoob eht ta namow ehT
.llac enohp elgnis a rewsna ton did narocroC tsuguA
.noyL leinahtaN dna
.mih fo tnorf ni saw tahw tuoba gnikniht tuohtiw
,sgnir fo tnuoma thgir eht retfA
,htped erom ni yrots eht tuoba klat ot evol d’I
,enimre eht rof tcepser ni daeh sih deppid
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.elihw a rof sesac yna gnikat eb t’ndluow eh taht dediced ecnaL
.mih fo tnorf ni egap eht no rehtegot seman esoht gniees
.mih dellik dah tahw wenk eh dna
,liame sih ot thgir mih thguorb hcihw
.denruter erofeb stnemom yawa depiw dah eh sraet eht
enohp sih ta yawa deppat ylkciuq eH
.detciderp evah dluow ecnaL sa ,retxet a ton saw eh dewohs
.esnopser eht dnA  tsuguA
,hguoht ,egrahc ot gniyrt ,tcaf ni ,saw ti taht mih ot detacidni edis eht no thgil ehT
narocroC tsuguA ,daetsni ,dna ,leinahtaN morf llac on saw ereht ,keew enO
ti htaenrednu redlof a
,erofeb stnemom tlef d’eh naht dehsilpmocca ssel raf gnileef mih tfel ecived eht no nrut ot gniyrt ,yletanutrofnU
.taht detapicitna dah ecnaL tub ,epoh taht fo emos dehsad
,xob a ni yawa neddih
.stros lla fo seirots dekil narocroC tsuguA
.yldab os yromem taht detnaw esle enoemos taht epoh detaes-peed emas eht dleh reyD ecnaL dna
,hguoht ,skoob esoht fo eno ni debrosba ylbativeni flesmih gnidnif erofeB
,meht tcatnoc ot euneva tseb eht dna desaeced eht fo snosrep detcatnoc tsom eht
,enohp sih tuo dellup eh ,daetsnI
.nwot fo edis rehto eht no tsuj
,dellepmoc saw ecnaL ,os
niaga uoy htiw hcuot ni gnitteg tuoba erom erac I taht dediced osla I
.noitacav a ekat d’eh spahreP
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
saw ti spahrep ro ,ytilauxes sih fo esuaceb ylno fi
,erom ecno no devom ecnaL
.oot ,ksat a mih evag dael tahT
nam eht pu edam taht serutaef eht fo noitamaglama nA
,mih tpek taht ecnamor saw tI
.mih htiw emoh krow sih thguorb eh esuaceb
,taht denrael tub
.tsil tcatnoc a ni dnif thgim eno stcepsus lausu eht fo enon dedleiy meht hguorht nacs kciuq A
,skoobtxet esoht ot txen thgir ylbaborp
.ti dnuof dah eh erehw kcab ylefas ti dekcut dna
enecs a morf yawa deklaw eh
ton ylniatrec saw ti tub
.saw eh lla s’taht ,tnemom a roF .etihw bard
,tub ,diputs elttil a si siht gnidnes taht won gnizilaer m’I
,repmihw a lufrewop os tlef reven dah reyD ecnaL
,dne eht dehcaorppa eh sa retsaf tog tsuj gnidaer s’ecnaL
,yaw eht devap ohw esoht rof dah narocroC tsuguA taht
.setaicossa nwonk ro sevitaler gnivil oN
.ekil d’uoy revetahw ,yrotsih tnemyolpme ,sserdda na ,eman A
tubed rieht gnikam si ohw ,aneY irA yb
,yaw gnorw eht tsuj ni gut tsethgils eht tsuj htiw trapa kaerb dluoc ti hguoht sa ti gnitaert niaga
htiw railimaf saw eh taht sdem esoht fo emos deveileb ylniatrec ecnaL tub
,noitnetta emas eht drow yreve evig ot detnaw ecnaL  .emoh kcab fo
.lla dna ,seye krad
gnitirwdnah eht ,ti nO
fo ecioV ehT no
.enimre eht tuoba gnitcepsus neeb dah eh tahw fo noitamrifnoc ot elbissop sa esolc sa
.spets tnatropmi tsom eht fo eno saw siht taht wenk ecnaL
noitpircserp hcae fo setad dne eht
,mih rebmemer ,dluoc ro ,dluow esle ydobon fI
,thgiarts denottub ,trihs deralloC
gnitrats rof delttes tub ,tnes yeht drow yreve daer ot detnaw ecnaL .esnopser a
,nwo sih erew ehs fi sa duorp saw tsuguA dna
.emit emos nrubuA tuoba uoy ot klat ot evol d’I
.etelpmoc %001 sa detacidni eno yreve dna hcae ,tums erup ylraen erew taht seirots sselemahs esoht neve
.tsuguA ,uoy htiw hcuot ni kcab teg ot dediced I dalg m’I
.wenk eh ,mih rof eb dluow ti esrow eht saw eh retal eht os
,yltpurba emac owt eht neewteb degnahcxe egassem lanif ehT
,ylper ot meht fo eno rof syad wef a koot ti semitemoS
efil eht rof noitaicerppa wen a dah osla eh tuB
,cirbaf yvaeh ,tfos eht devom eh nehW
?stcatnoc 01 naht ssel dah eh nehw
,yrots ecnamor hcus eno dehsinif tsuj dah narocroC tsuguA demees ti
.boj eht no snoitalutargnoC .)yldnof yrev
.doog emos narocroC tsuguA enod evah thgim
.dnuora gnigammur saw eh tnemtrapa nwo sih erew siht fi
.uoy fo kniht tub pleh t’nac I dna ,erotskoob reeuq elttil elbaroda siht ssap I
,yteixna ,noisserped fo seman eht ezingocer ot werg ecnaL os
.emit emos nrubuA tuoba raeh ot evol d’I
,htiw nekops reve dah eh wef yrev eht fo emos erew yeht taht gnidnatsrednu ni dna
dlrow a ni dna
xof retirw gnuoy a neewteb eno
,ytiroirp pot s’enimre eht ton saw ssenilnaelc sti taht raelc saw ti ,yas ot si tahT
,neeb evah tsum tI .lufituaeb
koob a daer dah eno semitemos dna
.tnemtrapa sih ni enola deiD
.serusaert owt tub
,kcab leinahtaN deliame dah eh fI
,yad yreve krow ot yaw ym nO
.liameciov ot tnes saw eh
.ti evil dna tuo og ot detnaw eh dna ,gnivil saw eh
,narocroC tsuguA fo tnemtrapa eht ni
,lrig retto gnuoy a fo
,dna ,dne eht wenk eh thguoht ecnaL
,yad txen eht kcab dellac
.dias eciov s’namow a ”,olleH“
.dexif teg ot hguone tnatropmi ton tub ,lacirtemmysa
,ytilaer taht htiw ecaf ot ecaf ,woN
narocroC tsuguA tuB
.tnemgduj sih gniduolc neeb
.repmihw a ylno emac ereht
.sisponys eht morf rehtag dluoc ecnaL tahw saw taht ,tsael tA
srebmun enohp degnahcxe yehT
yrots taht esuaceb
,seman enicidem dna
,loohcs hgih detrats accebeR
.wen gnihtemos ekam ot woh nrael ot teg I os ,fo draeh reven ev’I knird a gnitnaw ni semoc enoemos ,thgin yrevE
,dloh lla ew hcihw etaf emas eht
.flesmih ti llac ot eb dluow noitamrifnoc fo tros yna eviecer ot yaw ylno eht dna
.erar ylriaf saw noitacinummoc sa
ecived eht fo sedis nwod nrow ehT
.kcab edaced a revo llew gniog
,smees eh sa yag sa s’eh fi ,hguohT
,ecneirepxe s’ecnaL ni ,esuaceb
neeb evah tsum tI
.enog saw enimre eht taht nettogrof tsomla dah dna
,hguoht ,sllac rieht pu kcip dna ,llac yllanoisacco d’eh ,srotcoD
,erofeb enoyna naht
,eloh taht morf tuo dehcnarb eh
.slleb on gnar rebmun enohp siht tub ,seno lacol ylralucitrap ,sedoc aera fo hcum wenk eh thguoht ecnaL
,mih noitnem uoy raeh ot ecin s’ti os ,yllautca ,nodnarB fo em sdnimer rehtaf ehT .ti ni tned a gnikam ylwols neeb ev’I tub
.emit a ta sdrow fo sderdnuh fo egnahcxe lausu eht morf raf saw ti dna
efil ot emac htob
ycavirp fo yaw eht ni deen
,ereht gnikrow ydal eht dna
.emit siht lla retfa ,uoy morf raeh ot deveiler yllaer ,yllaer saw I
,emit emos retfa sliame eht deteled yltnenamrep knuj naht rehtar hsart eht ot meht gnidnes taht nwonk evah ton thgim tsuguA
.retteb hcum teg ot gniog t’nsaw ylbaborp ti dediced I
2 traP ,aneY irA yb
,delif krowrepap eht lla
.niereht enicidem eht fo seman eht fo yna ezingocer t’ndid ecnaL .daer t’ndluoc
dootsrednu reven eh tahW
,tlef eh woh wenk uaessuoR fi taht wenk eH
moor sih ni enola daer eh slevon yretsym eht saw eH
.retal ti ot nruter ot elba eb thgim eh taht sepoh eht ni nwod ti tes ecnaL os
ylbakatsimnu saw ti tub
,remrof eht naht etad-ot-pu erom raf rettal eht ,redaere na dna ,enohp llec A
ecnaL ot delaever gnihcraes rehtruF
,lla ta xobni eht ni egassem tseilrae eht ,erus m’I ,dna ,tsrif ehT
aedi eugav a dah ylno llits dna
,leinahtaN morf llac a eb dluow ereht
,lla ti wonk t’ndid eh elihw
.tluacuoF lehciM dna ,kliM yevraH ,ecarebiL ,yrucreM eidderF no esoht
pael a hcus ekam ot tnaw t’ndid eh tub ,esruoc fo ,boj sih fo trap a erew snoitpmussA
,noitanitsed sih yb denifed ton saw
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,ti tuoba klat ot tnaw uoy ediced dna ti daer ot ediced uoy fi dna
tsuj uoY .lla retfa dab os eb ton thgim slevon cihparG
,krow fo enil s’ecnaL ni rehtag dluoc uoy noitamrofni tnatropmi tsom eht ,nip s’nosrep a sseug dluoc uoy fI .tsrif enohpllec eht deirt eH
,remmilg thgils taht gnileef llits ,thguoht eh ,sihT
,revo dna revo daer neeb dah ti taht morf trapa
.yas yeht sa gnitseretni sa s’ti dna
,wols saw tI .did tI
.elpoep htiw taerg neeb syawla ev’uoY
.kcab mih gnirb dluoc yrots sih gnidnatsrednu ro mih rof gnirac fo tnuoma oN
emit tsal eno yrt d’I thguoht I dna
.ycnegreme na sa yfilauq llew yrev dluoc
,noertaP rieht no krow rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY .goD
.nodnarB naht em ekil erom si rehtaf eht ebyam
,saw eh thguoht yeht ohw tsuj saw narocroC tsuguA taht lerriuqs eht llet dluow eH
.em ot ti ebircsed ot nageb dna gnikool em was
.reraen werg dne eht sa dna
spahrep ro ,etalosi fles ot ycnednet a dah osla
,gnihton ,yltpurba ,dnA
.erofeb nees evah reven d’eh elgna na ta
.stenibac enicidem esoht fo eno
,dedeen fi secivres ycnegreme eht rof laid deeps a flesmih gnivig fo yaw ciahcra s’nam dlo na saw ,demussa eh ,tahT ’.ycnegremE‘
ypoc a thguob osla I tub
,enimre eht ni flesmih ees dluoc eh esuaceb saw ti spahreP
dnoces eht saw sihT
’ycnegremE‘ ’.ycnegremE‘ ot llac eno
,esuaceb ,erom elttil a tsuj
,sseltiurf devorp no ti nrut ot gniyrt dna ni ti gniggulp nevE
.psarg ruoy ni thgir saw
,eb thgim rebmun eht tahw detcepsus eH
,dne eno no buthtab a htiw ,llams
.syad regnuoy sih ni ,ecanem a neeb evah thgiM
.mih rof dekcolnu enohp eht
.deneppah tahw wonk ot dedeen eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,aneY irA yb
,ecnednopserroc fo seceip eerht tsrif rieht nevig dah eh taht
.rebmun enohp laer a saw tI .lla
retupmoc a gnidih neeb evah tsum narocroC tsuguA
.enola srebmun yb ees dluoc reyD ecnaL sa raf sa ,tsael ta
degnoleb taht gninrael ni lla ta esirprus on tlef ecnaL ,pu ti gnikool nopu ,deedni ,dnA
.neeb evah ecno tsum
,thguoht eh ,tuo krow t’ndid potpal eht fI
,sraey dna sraey kcab gniog ,potpal eht desu reve ylno dah narocroC tsuguA taht
…raf os eulc gnisimorp tsom eht eb tsuj yam rettel dlo nA
emoh sih tfel reve yldrah ohw nam a dluow tahw ,dnA
.skoob fo revoL .nam yag duorP
,uoy ot ti sekam siht fi
,yawa klaw ot ydaer saw eh sA
.nrubuA fo brubus a ot
.taht saw taht dna ,daed saw narocroC tsuguA
,gniga sih ni eb ot mih deliforp dah ecnaL
;oot ,erneg etirovaf a dah narocroC tsuguA .nwo sih fo
,elttil a tsuj ,flesmih gnisirprus ,elzzum nwo sih htiw tem saw
,stfut rae ,ruf naT
,lla ti hguorht kniht ot gnitnaw
,kool ot erehw tsuj wenk ,saw eh taht trepxe ,reyD ecnaL .erehwemos os od ot hcihw htiw
.rehto hcae eripsni dna pleh ot elba gnieb ni dnuof yeht gniht lufituaeb eht dna
,ynam ,ffo nrot ,revo depat ,pu depat neeb dah rorrim eht no repap eht ,teY
,llac enohp elgnis a derewsna reven tsomla narocroC tsuguA
ecaf ot ecaf mih thguorb tahT
,sngis rehto yna rof koob eht hguorht debmuht ecnaL
,rof dedeen saw eh ohw esoht tsgnoma daerht nommoc a eb ot demees erehT
.emac ti nehw seye sih ni esirprus eht dna
,nwo sih fo yrarbil a rof moor hcum evah t’ndid eh dnA .saw
,sneppah ti sa ,dna ,rorrim eht desolc dah
.dne eht ni yppah saw yrots yreve ton taht wenk reyD ecnaL
narocroC tsuguA sa
,moor eht ni dnim ni ksat eno tsuj dah eH .ni devil
tsrif sih dah eH
,meht fo gnidnatsrednu etamitni na hcus deriuqer ti ,teY
.mih fo edisni epoh fo remmilg emos htiw llits