,deralced ehs ”,desirprus eb lliw uoY“
,ytiniffA ruF no dnuof eb nac tra dna seirots esohw stnelat ynam fo esroh ecnassianeR a
.dne eht ni ylefas emoh teg uoy erus ekam dna uoy fo erac ekat ll’I
,owt eht fo remaerd eht dna
”.su retfa kool dog tresed ruoy tel dna
.eurt s’taht lla sees eulb fo eye ehT     orevO ovitlA yb
”,sreppoc xis dna revlis owt ylno
”,gnola uoy tuohtiw emas eht eb t’ndluow tI“
,kcod eht no ro kced no ylisub gnikrow sruf rolias eht gnihctaw dna
,tsirw sih no gnoleb ot demees won taht telecarb eht ta gnirats ,dias eh
,sllems dna sthgis egnarts eht
.sevlesmeht spihs eht ot sriaper gnikam ro
,riap eht fo citsilaer dna lacitcarp erom eht yllausu dna xof der a ,cenneF
.elavtseW ot kcab
.cenneF ot telecarb eht evag ,elims thgirb a htiw dna ,deddon ehS
.dneirf etehtsea sih rof naht
”,erutseg dnarg a saw tahT“
.tsev wen sih fo renroc a htiw ti dehsilop dna
.sreppoc owt dna revlis a tuo werd dna
,pirt siht fo noitapicitna ni raey a rof snioc devas dah yehT
,dneps ot nioc revlis elgnis a detegdub ylno dah
.noinapmoc sih ot tuo wap a dleh dna reh ta dekniw eh tub
evolg a ekil mih tif dluow ti taht mih derussa tnahcrem ehT
mih rof tneuqerf ssel hcum esnopser lanoitome na
,mih dereets dna wap eht yb sogrA koot neht
.elbaromem gnihtemos yub ot droffa dluoc hcae os
.kaeps ot hguone llew flesmih derevocer yllanif flow eht
daor eht otno swaptoof rieht denrut dna
ksid dehsilop ,talf a saw ereht retnec eht nI
,ecno ta aes retniw a dna yks remmus a ekil dekool tI
pihsdneirf ruo taht
”.erom emos ti tuoba kniht retteb d’I sseug I“ ,dettimda eh
yldaorb gniggaw saw liat s’cenneF
.revewoh ,raed saw ecirp ehT
,rehtegot su fo htob htrow si ti erus m’I ,ssertsim ,hA“
sogrA morf seye reh koot reven ohw ,nooccar ylredle na saw
,hguoht ,tsev eht no tup eh nehW
.slatem suoicerp thguorw-ylenif eht ylno
.meht fo htob rof tuobanrut fo dnik wen dna egnarts a saw tI
.cenneF ot wob elttil lufecarg a htiw
sgniht emos sa llew sa elbanigami gnihtyreve htiw dellif dna
neerg peed ni noitcefrep ot deyd
,ylthgils gniggaw yllautca liat dna
mih ot ton ekops ehs sa
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,mih dlot ehs ”,tneserp ot sruoY“
,secalkcen dna sgnir erew erehT
.mih ta dennirg tsuj cenneF
,dlog ni tseb eht dedivorp stnahcrem eseht taht suoivbo saw ti sa
ecarbme sih morf sogrA desaeler eh sa
,ton ro dog tresed eht fo ngised eht yb rehtehW
.ylisae os hctip selas revelc eht tsiser t’ndluoc eh tub
,esoohc ot emit koot tI
”.raeh dna ees ot tsuj tnuocsid eht htrow saw tahT
”.seye eulb emosdnah sih sehctam ti woh eeS“
,ereh fo htuos selim derdnuh evif
,esrup sih rof dehcaer eH .delims cenneF dna
,resolc deppets ehs sa gnilkraps seye krad reh
spihs lufrednow esoht fo eno draoba ngis ot egru eht htiw dezies flesmih dnuof
.eletneilc yhtlaew a ot
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.elbanoitseuqnu saw yalpsid no yrlewej eht fo yrtsitra ehT
.maof ro duolc eb thgim taht
.wap rehto eht fo hsiruolf a htiw ,dedda ehs
,ecalp ni yleruces ti esolc ot psalc kcirt eht dekrow eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.flesti fo snioc revlis eerht naht erom hgiew thgim ti fi sa dekool ti dna
.derewsna eh ”,t’now eW“
,orevO ovitlA yb
,krowtonk fo yrecart etaciled a htiw desahc saw latem ehT
,revlis eht nopu dehtaerb cenneF
.dlrow eht ssorca enotsyks eulb eht daerps ot sdog rieht ot ytud a sa ti ees yeht esuaceb ylpaehc krow rieht lles yeht dnA“ .dettimda ehs
”,retsul sti gnillud tuohtiw
,aes ot tuo gniog fo aedi eht ta elbatrofmocnu tlef
flow etihw a ,sogrA
”.llet lliw uoy tahw morf smaerd ym evaew
,yalpsid ralucricimes eht fo dne eht dehcaer dah yeht nehW
selbat yalpsid dehctaw ylluferac eht gnola deklaw dna
,delims nooccar ehT
,dneirf sih dexaoc cenneF ”,yetihW ,nom’C“
.evila niamer llits dna eert a nac naht meht morf yawa tuc eb erom on nac dna ,stoor evah I
”.emit lla rof tsal yam
,derewsna ohw sogrA saw tI .gnihsulb
.niaga hsulb dna knilb mih dehctaw dna
.yltnatcepxe dehctaw dna
,elzzum sih fo ruf trohs eht hguorht thgir gniwohs knip eht
,ecnedive ni saw reppoc ro ssarb oN
,laem a pu gnivig tnaem sreppoc eht dna
.poord liat sih tel dna srae sih denettalf sogrA
senots suoicerp dna ,revlis
.sreppoc owt dna revlis eno ot nwod relles eht gnitteg ni dedeeccus eh ,klat hcum retfA
.rae sih gnilzzun
,kniw rehtona htiw
dna spihs llat eht ta kool ot ,nottahC ot pirt taht edam yeht nehw loohcs fo tuo tsuj dna gnuoy erew yehT brevorP narákiH–                                                                                          !uoy sehctaw ti rof ,lli on uoht oD
.revelc era snasitra narákiH ehT“
yletaidemmi llef srae ’sogrA
,tsrif keehc ’sogrA ot txen ti dleh ehS
",ovitlA" sa onimA yrruF dna ,lysaeW
,stekram suomaf eht drawot dna
.tuo denrut dah yad eht yaw eht htiw deifsitas ylluf
:yojne esaelP .orevO ovitlA rednu nozamA no dna
,llew mih detius roloc eht taht dna
,dog a fo eye eht si esiouqrut eht yas yehT
”.snekot-evol fo evorppa I .owt dna owT“
sirraF“ gnidaer rennab a htiw eno ot emac yeht litnu srelaed detnioppa ylhcir erom eht gnoma yaw rieht deunitnoc yehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”doG treseD eht fo
.enola snioc revlis eerht sa hcum sa tsael ta hgiew ot raeppa dluow taht tuB“ ,deksa eh os
,daerb rof sreppoc tsal rieht dneps ot pohs s’rekab a ta desuap yehT
,flesmih ekil ,dneirf sih taht wenk eH
.evirra dluow ti hcihw ot llac fo strop tnatsid dna citoxe eht ees dna
retnec eht raen tniop a ot kcab deddap dna denrut sogrA
,ecarbme feirb a otni flow etihw eht dellup eh taht htiW
.htoob eht morf ,dezad
,erutnevda eht fo knihT
.telecarb revlis a ta erom ecno kool ot
dna ereh yats ll’I
,ylpeed dehsulb sogrA ,siht tA
.nooccar eht ot ti dessap ohw
”doG treseD eht fo eyE eulB ehT“
.cenneF ot denrut dna
eslup s’traeh nwo ruoy htiw mraw ti peeK
yllufepoh dekrep sraE
.ti tuoba lla em llet dna kcab emoc ot esimorp tub ,og uoY
”?reppus dna sgnigdol rof yap ew lliw woh tuB“
cenneF ot nioc revlis sih dednah dna
,deretnuoc ehs ”,rufeltneg gnuoy ,uoy roF“
,nekops lleW !ovarB“ dias dna
edis a no elim a tsomla
.psalc eht netsaf ton did ehs hguoht
htaerb gnivil s’flow eht tlef xof eht sa
.riaf eguh sti htiw lavitsef remmusdim eht yojne ot dna
.noitanigami eht deraggeb taht
,wap rehto eht nO
.ruf nwo sih otni ylmrif ti gnisserp
,nwo reh ni wap tfel s’flow etihw eht ekat ot tuo dehcaer ehs nehT
”.erusaert a hcus gniweiv fo erusaelp eht rof ylerem uoy knaht I tub
tsirw sih otno elbuab eht deppils ylgnirad dah ,hsalf a ni dna
esrup nwo sih otni dehcaer sogrA
si yrots s’yadot dna
.yalpsid reh ni ecalp sti morf telecarb eht dekculp ehs sa
.slevart sti no ylefas pihs eht ediug ot nus eht dna srats eht ylno htiw
”,deR ,os kniht t’nod I
.sgnidnib klis htiw demmirt dna
wap nwo reh ni kcab yllacigam saw telecarb ehT
smra s’cenneF ni yllufecaep tpels sogrA .sdnorf nref fo
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ris gnuoy ,dednetni retteb neve dna
.tib a ekahs eciov sih edam mih nihtiw erised ehT ”?hcum woH“
srats eht rednu peels ot gniog er’eW“
”doG treseD eht fo eyE eulB ehT“ saw sihT
,spihs eht ta dekool deedni dah yehT
,orevO ovitlA ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
,ksa ot derad sogrA
,erutseg esirprus a ni ,nehT
”.swaptoof ruoy htaeneb dlrow elohw a
,ecalptekram eht fo egde eht dehcaer dah yeht nehW
revo ylgnignol denael eh erehw
elbat ralucitrap taht fo egrahc ni relles ehT
,ylbmuN .detpmorp eh
”,rufeltneg gnuoy ,ytilauq rof eye tnellecxe na sah noinapmoc emosdnah ruoY“ .cenneF ot tub
.tsetorp ot htuom sih nepo sogrA gnihctaw
.swaptoof reh htaeneb tsud eht hguorht ti gniggard diova ot hguone tsuj liat depirts ylhsul reh gnitfil
,espalloc srae sih tlef nrut ni cenneF
.taoc der nwo sih dna seye sih fo dlog eht ffo tes ti sa
eyE eulB ehT“yojne esaelP
,yaw a was eh thguoht eh dnA
.reraew sti revo hctaw syawla lliw taht
.ti wenk yeht erofeb elbat yalpsid eht no kcab delttes dna
.rufeltneg yhtlaew a fo ecnaraeppa dna ria eht cenneF evag ti dna
,kool delzzup a mih evag ssertsim ehT
,ograc gnidaolnu dna gnidaol
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,dereffo gnieb sdoog eht fo erutan eht mialcorp ot deen ton did ngis ehT ”.notliW dna
,yltpurba dereffo eh ”,srevlis owT“
deb yrd a no rehtegot delruc thgin elbatrofmoc dna mraw a tneps sdneirf owt eht
,traeh sih tsniaga ti dleh eh
.levart rof edam ton tsuj m’I“ .derewsna eh
,tsev loow enif a nopu delttes dah erised s’traeh sih taht dnuof yllautneve cenneF
”?elttil os rof lles ti nac woH
skcod eht morf yawa selzzum rieht denrut yehT
,sevlesruoy sa srufeltneg enif hcus roF“
.spuc gniknird neve dna stelecarb
,noitcerid reh ni wob lacirtaeht a fo hcteks elttil a edam xof ehT
.ecniw neve t’ndid cenneF tub ,seye eulb sih fo tuo tnew thgil eht dna
?naem uoy swaptoof ym htaeneb naeco eritne nA“
”,taocruf sseltops sih tsniaga llew os stis ti dnA“
.lessev emas eht no rehtegot pu ngis nac eW“
noilivap eht deretne sselehtenon yeht ,hcus droffa dluoc meht fo rehtien taht gniwonK
.dneirf raed ,traeh ym fo htmraw ehT“ gniyas
.mih ta dekniw nooccar ehT
.ereht ecalp ni telecarb eht deppils dna
,revlis eht flesmih detegdub dah xof ehT
”.dnegel ytterp a ylniatrec si ti ,ton ro eurT
,yllufhturt nekops dah tnahcrem ehT
”.esiouqrut narákiH enif a si enots eht dna
.ylgniwonk deddon nooccar ehT
,pu denethgiarts flow eht sa delkcuhc cenneF
,slias delruf dna stsam llat eht ta gnirats
.elims ot dah dneirf sih neve
.esimorp I ,mih rof tfig retteb on dnif dluoc uoY“ .mih dlot ehs
yvaeh dna gnorts ti ekam ot revlis eht htiw reppoc hguone tsuj dnelb ot woh wonk yehT
nwo sih ni wap tfel ’sogrA koot eh nehw demraw dah latem looc ehT
.wap a htiw yllufthguoht elzzum sih gnibbur ,dias eh
,nwot trop eht fo srednow rehto eht
,ffur tsehc nwo sih tsniaga
.shtoob dna stnet lufroloc eht ni dereffo seraw eht fo noitanimaxe hcum dna
.lavorppasid ni no dekool sogrA elihw snioc eht revo dednah ylevislupmi eh tub
etihw fo skaerts ynit htiw
”?sogrA ,revlis ruoY“
,dias nooccar eht
.eulb fo edahs lufrednow tsom eht fo
.meht dniheb yletilop depsalc swap rieht htiw
,tsaoc tresed eht morf semoc dnab tahT
rehtegot swap reh deppalc nooccar ehT
”,elat ytterp a ,deednI“ .deddon cenneF