tac eht ekil kool ti edam noitanigami siH
yawyna sevolg eht dedderhs tsuj evah dluow dna sevolg raew ot swalc sih deraperp t’ndah eh—no meht llup ot rehtob t’ndid eH
,mih tfel sthguoht tsal sih dna
.srae sih neewteb dna
esproc a pu denaelc ylluf ,pu dewohs
,mih drawot deklats ti ,ecnelis rettu nI
oehT ta dnah a devaw drawetS
.metsys yrotcaflo sih rof derevoc ylhguoroht oot saw ti
”.emoh teg ot reh rof gnitiaw ,yad lla ereh
,rewoT leffiE eht fo pot eht ta sotohp erew erehT
a htiw ,tseb ta ,thgieh egareva saw eh
,tnemevorpmi emos ees ot detrats dah aera eht ,edam neeb dah rac s’drawetS taht emit eht dnuora erehwemoS
,rood eht dloh ot reh deksa eh nehw drawetS ta gnicnalg ylerab
.hcum taht niatnoc dluoc nosrep elgnis a kniht t’ndid eh hguoht
.tisiv roirp fo kram a hcae
,gnidliub eht otni em zzub ot enoyna teg t’ndluoc I“
.mra reppu sih otni peed deppir dna
.ytic eht fo trap mirg a saw siht gniyned on saw erehT
.yrd dna hgih noitalupop eht tfel dna
,gnihtemos draeh I ,llew …a draeh I
,wollof dluoc drawetS naht retsaf devom eH
rodirroc lamron ylsuourgnocni eht otni dna rotavele eht fo tuo gnippets erofeb
.rekihhctih flowerew
,tnemtrapa eht sdrawot detfird oehT sa knuks eht dniheb deliart drawetS
.nus eht ni egawes ekil
.moordeb a otni dereep eh sa
.yvaeh os tlef llits ydob sih ,htaed saw siht fi ,yhw gnirednow
,gnippat ydaets eht morf edisA
”?gniod er’uoy tahw fo gnilkni tsael eht evah uoy oD“
”,snosaer lausu eht rof ,dnabsuh reh yb namow a liat ot derih tog I“
.eerga ot denilcni saw drawetS
.dnim on mih diap oehT tub ,smraerof s’knuks eht ta dewalc dna dehctarcs drawetS
”?taht wonk ylbissop uoy dluoc woH“
sluos tsol os ro nezod a fo sehsalf feirb thguac drawetS
”.ni eveileb t’ndid ehs taht gnihtemos yb trapa deppir
lufecaep saw epacsthgin eht tub ,sthgil wolley dna eulb gnihsalf ees ot gnitcepxe ,wodniw moordeb eht tuo decnalg eH
gninetsil saw eh wohs ot
.sevolg xetal fo tes dlo na dnuof eh litnu taoc sih hguorht gniggid erofeb
.otohp yreve ni erab saw regnif gnir reH
,yllautcelletni ,wenk eH
.hcuoc eht fo tnorf ni paeh a ni dednal eH
”.flesym krowrepap eht lla dekcehc I .egairram eht fo foorp gnitteg tuohtiw siht ekil boj a ekat t’nod I“
.deton eh ,won ffo erew yehT
.ssorca pael ot gib oot doolb fo elddup a eb ot ereht derebmemer drawetS erehw sdrawot
,doolb eht fo ngis on
.wodniw eht fo edistuo ytic eht fo thgil eugav eht dna swodahs ni til
.mih detius ti dna ,nam suoromalg a t’nsaw drawetS tub
.moor gnivil eht morf nehctik eht gnitarapes rab eht revo mih dessot
?desirprus saw ehs ,tahw ,os ,yakO“
nedrag gnitivninu na saw tI
,snoitagitsevni emirc suoires evif spahrep ni devlovni flesmih dnuof dah drawetS
.dlrowrednU ehT   .kni.sfhf ta elbaliava
,oehT ta gnirats llits ,eveels sih fo kcab eht no eson sih debbur eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,hsart eht dniheb llaw eht nO
.erom neve demmid noisiv sih dna ,mih hguorht denrub niap toh-etihw gniraeS
,sucof ot elbanu seye sih
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.bonk eht ta gnihcnerw ,rood eht ot dehsad dna teef sih ot delbmarcs eH .nur
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tsopdeb a no delgnat gnitteg sgel sih fo eno
”.gnikaeps fo rennam a nI“ ”?neht ,rellik ehT“
.derevihs drawetS divaD
,despalloc drawetS
taht tuP“ ”…siht dnuof I ,kooL“
.mih ta dekool oehT revenehw yerp ekil tlef syawla drawetS taht saw tI
.kcart ot hguone raelc ro gnorts enon
:dnammoc elpmis eno ydob sih evag
srorroh elbawonknu hcus fo ecaf eht ni deniamer dnim s’drawetS fo trap lanoitar revetahW
.tius krad sih ni hctap tew gnidaerps a revo tsehc sih gnihctulc mra eno
,ecaf sih morf yawa sehcni saw oehT ,yltpurbA
.deneppah dah ti taht llet t’ndluoc uoy ,dellips yllautca saw doolb erehw aera eht dehcaer uoy litnu dna
.dlrowrednu mret eht fo sesnes evitcepser rieht ot
.hguone tsaf ton tub ,swalc s’tac eht rednu dekcud drawetS
,gnihtyna od ot ,epacse ot
daed dewollahnu eht dna ,ssenkrad ,sretsnom fo mlaer a ot
.mih lewobmesid ot ydaer ees t’ndluoc eh swalc prahs-rozar ,desiar dnah eno
.esaelp ,evitceteD“
taht euqisyhp dnuor tahwemos
.serutcip emos koot I ,tac a
,repap saw ti hguoht sa taoc kciht sih hguorht decils yehT
lobmys egnarts a saw
,evah dluohs eh tsael ta rO
.ezingocer ton did eh tebahpla egnarts a htiw dellif sexetrev eht
.enips s’drawetS nwod revihs rehtona tnes
.deb ruoy rednu sretsnom eht etagorretni ot teg t’nod uoy
”.no esitrepxe laiceps ruoy esu dluoc I esproc fo tros eht s’ti dnA
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht fo rebmem duorp A
pu mih dekcip dah oehT
.tnemtrapa eht sdrawot denrut oehT
,wodniw eht sdrawot gniylf
.dnuorg eht tsniaga gnirettalps der gnimossolb eht
.gniees saw eh tahw dneherpmoc ot shtaerb eerht drawetS koot tI
.dica ekil denrub dnuow ehT
.ees ot ton dneterp ot sreferp tser eht
”?tegrat ruoy ti saW“ .mih dewollof dna erows drawetS
,roolf dna sllaw eht dennacs drawetS
hguoht ,edamdnah ,ti fo kool eht yb ,dna nori
.ecnalg drawkcab a sa hcum os tuohtiw sriats eht rof dedaeh dna
.deeps elbissopmi emas eht ,ecnelis emas eht htiw gnivom
.rood s’mitciv eht fo tnorf ni gnidnats sevlesmeht dnuof yeht ,ylkciuq ooT
,dessap eh sa nehctik eht otni decnalg eH
”?dnabsuh reh fo sotohp yna ereht t’nera yhW“
,semit evif roirp eht dah eh sa ,flesmih deleets drawetS ,sselehtreveN
,mih drawot gnivom ydaerla saw knuks ehT
htlaew eht tuo delgnarts dah
”,ydlom erew sehsid ehT“
”?evitceted ,em ees ot dehsiw uoY“  2 fo 1 traP ,enrohtwaH .S.J yb
,uaeb reh htiw emac ehS
,nosaer emos rof dil nac hsart eht devomer dah oehT taht saw thguoht tsrif siH
,era yeht woh wonk uoY .detagorretni eb ot dnuora kcits t’ndid I tub ,esruoc fO“
”.emit eno neppah taht dah I ,snossel ecnad ekiL .suouconni gnihtemos ton dna ,wonk uoy
.eb ot desoppus neeb evah yeht sa
,teerts ytrid eht no paeh a ot llef ohw
nosaer eht saw ohw tneilc a fo xe yrgna eht gnidulcni
,eutats a sa llits sa ,desuap eh erehT
,serutcip fo elpuoc a koot dna snaej sih fo tuo enohpllec sih deppils eH
yteicos fo strap revetahw ot dna
,doolb saw desseug drawetS tahw yb
eht taht etartsnomed lliw yeht thginot tuB
,gnitaolf saw eh neht dnA
.kniht ot emit saw ereht dna ,wols saw tI
— 5002 1 yaM —
”.siht ees dluohs uoY
.gniliar eht ta pu derats
,meht fo tsom fo ytilauq roop eht edih ot
.gninetsil saw eh wohs ot detnurg knuks ehT
tac sseldaeh eht—epahs ehT
,knuks eht dewollof eh ,lworg tnelis a htiW
,gnidliub eht otni meht tel nooccar lufpleh A .dehgis drawetS
.esrow gnitteg saw egabrag gnittor fo llems knar eht
.meht erofeb rorroh eht fo ecaf eht ni mlac eb dluoc eh woh rof ssol a ta ylrettu
.ereht dednal evah dluoc ti
.dias oehT ”,evitceted
.enilerohs yesreJ weN eht fo sthgil gnilkniwt eht dna
.ti enod d’yeht gnizilaer neve tuohtiw
.etagitsevni ot degreme dah stnediser rehto eht fo enon tub ,tuoba tsac flow ehT
.esac tsrif sih sevlos eh woh dna
,dednetxe erew swalc sti—siH
raey taht yadhtrib nwo sih derebmemer eH
.reveostahw dnuos on edam ti
gnihtaerb llits saw
sllaw eht ro dnuorg eht otni mih gnimmals dna swalc ekil-rozar sti htiw knuks eht ta gnihsals saw llits tub ,mih dnuora teg ot gnitpmetta ylno ,oehT mrah ot gniyrt eb ot mees t’ndid gniht ehT
.mih no nwod dnecsed neht dna yawa gniht-tac eht evohs ti was eH
wolg eht gnikatsim on saw erehT
revir eht fo noziroh krad eht neve dna enilyks eht fo weiv doog a dah dah reed ehT .debrutsidnu dna
.debrutsid ylsselerac ev’uoy hcihw eulc A“ ”.em ot
.noitseuq derewsnanu eht ot esnopser ni daeh sih koohs ohw
.noitalupop dna htlaew htob fo noisolpxe evissam a nees dah doohrobhgien eht
,reed eht fo mrof nekorb dna detsiwt eht derebmemer dnim sih ,neddibnU
ro tnurg neve ro
,enips reh fo elgna larutannu eht
.deddon oehT ”?erus uoY“
,oehT ta decnalg eH
”?daed saw ehs erus
.egalfuomac fo tib elbakramer a saw tI
,erutplucs eci na sa llits ,oehT sa ecnelis elbatrofmocnu ,gnol a saw erehT
.eson sih debbur drawetS
yadhtriB yppaH“ htiw dehsalps draobllib cinortcele na htaeneb gnisop eno neve dna
.deb eht ta delialf eh sa yvaeh dna
,gniksa rof delttes drawetS
,neeb dah hcamots s’tac eht erehw hsag a morf rohci fo dnik emos fo pird eht fo
.tnecs on deirrac ti tub ,ti ta ylsuoituac deffins eH
.yranidro eht fo tuo dekool ylerar
,nepo dils srood rotavele eht neht dnA
sreciffo ecilop fo nordauqs a taht eveileb yltsenoh uoy oD
,neht dekcit setunim eht sa knuks eht dehctaw drawetS .seye sih fo
.lausu naht oserom ,lacinilc
.sotohp eht gninnacs ,desuap drawetS
,doolb fo tnecs yna saw ereht fI
.nosrep emas eht saw ti desseug evah t’ndluow eh ,gnineve taht reilrae retne tac eht nees t’ndah drawetS fI
.gnissim saw liat sih fo driht tsal eht
:stcaf owt eseht tpecca uoy
,nur dna pu teg ot mih ta demaercs niarb siH
”.taht ekil gnihtemos gnivivrus on s’ereht yas tsuj s’tel ,lleW“
.deppans oehT
.oga syad tuo nekat neeb evah dluohs taht hsart fo tnecs eht ta gnilknirw eson
.kcen sih fo daetsni ecaf sih ta hsals ot swalc eht rof hguone tsuj mih gnivom
”,doolb yna llems t’nod I“
,maws noisiv s’drawetS
yllabrev sserpxe ot gnilliwnu ,dnah sih htiw erutseg eugav a edam eH
,dloc saw eciov siH .dias oehT
,erif elap ,dloc a htiw gninrub seye
,won naelc saw tI
,em noitseuq ot teg ton od uoY“
,epacse erif eht morf ti deppord dah tnaliassa eht ro reed eht rehtie fI
.esuoh ronam tneicna eht fo swodahs eht ni
”.doolb on si erehT“
.rebmemer ,redrum a tuo erugif ot gniyrT“
.esuops rieht no taehc ot tegrat a rof tiaw ot
.dah neeb evah uoy spahrep tseggus dluow I“
”,elbissop ton s’tahT“
.level-dnuorg no saw sucof siH .dias drawetS
”.rovaf a deen I ,haeY“
”.reh saw ti wenk I sraluconib eht erofeb nevE .riah tnereffid evah owt rehto eht dna ,gnidliub eht ni evil ohw reed eerht ylno s’erehT .ti gnikatsim on
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
,sretaw laciport tnereffid nezod a ni sotohp retawrednu dab
.knuks eht no desucof ,yawa dekool eh dna
regnad fo swaj eht otni deniev-yci gniklaw tuoba tnereffid gnihtemos saw ereht tub
.kcab daeh sih gninarc ,deksa oehT
.tpecca ot niarb sih rof neila oot ylpmis saw—
.nosduH eht morf skcolb owt ylerab ,edis tsew eht no gnidliub tnemtrapa dlo na fo wodahs eht ni dekrap erew
tam kcalb ynihs a ni nwod deretsalp saw
,gninraw a dna lrans a htiw rood moordeb eht sdrawot mih devohs knuks eht tub ,dessap eh sa oehT barg ot depoots eH
,nehctik eht tsap ,moor gnivil natraps tahwemos ,taen eht hguorht thgiarts tnew tub ,drawetS rof tiaw ot deppots t’ndah oehT
”,rehtien ,eM“ .derumrum eh
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
”.tnemtrapa eht ni no emac sthgil eht
”?pu ti denaelc yeht ebyam kniht uoY“
eciffo s’rennalp nabru eht ni tfarg dna noitpurroc fo evaw a dna
.teef sih gniggard ylsuoicsnocnu saw drawetS esle ro ,hcterts ot demees yawllah eht tub ,rotavele eht morf sdray wef a ylno saw tI
.oehT ot tuo llac ot denrut neht
”?gniod er’uoy kniht uoy od tahW“
.rednerrus ni sdnah sih pu dleh dna esufer fo elip eht otni kcab pord lian eht tel drawetS
”,etunim a tiaW“ ”.tnarongi
.ekirts ot desiar swalc
.mih revo gnimool oehT dnif ot pu dekool drawetS
.dlrow eht ssorca lla stops tsiruot suomaf dewohs sotohp eht dna
.rood eht no drah evohs ot drawetS tsap dehcaer neht ,deggurhs oehT
.rood moorhtab eht evoba llaw eht otni demmals dna daeh sih revo welf oehT nehw moordeb eht htiw neve nettog tsuj dah eH
”?ydob eht was uoy nehw uoy erew erehW“
,mih sdrawot gnihsur tac eht ees ot denrut drawetS dna
eht fo llams eht ni kcurt egabrag a ekil mih tih thgiew dicnar a dna ,knuks eht ot dehctertstuo dnah eno ,detatiseh flow ehT .gnivomnu
,seninac s’knuks eht yllaicepse
.deggurhs tsuj knuks eht ,tnemom a retfa tub ,gnitarobale fo egrev eht no neeb evah thgim eh thguoht drawetS
.gnidliub tnemtrapa eht ta pu decnalg eH
.wodniw eht tuo kool ot yawa gninrut ,oehT dias
elbisiv ylraelc seye deroloc eci sih fo ecnecsenimul tniaf eht ylno
,ygrene sih fo sevreser tsal eht htiw
”,moor gnivil eht denaelc dna ,thginot etad a dah ehS“
,rebma fo edahs elbakramernu na fi
.esion a edam oehT ron ti rehtien
.swolb s’tac eht fo ecrof eht htiw psag
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ytiliga dna deeps elbidercni htiw tub
mih dniheb llits saw oehT taht derebmemer eh erofeb nehctik eht otni spets owt nekat dah eh dna
”.tey devirra ev’yeht kniht neve t’nod I
.emit erom yna ksir erad t’ndid drawetS dna
,gniht-tac eht htiw retnuocne sih devivrus sah drawetS woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.ytic eht ni ecalp tsrow eht morf raf saw ti
”.nwotpu yllaicepse ,nosaer ot netsil t’now dna aedi na teg yeht
.rood eht sdrawot denrut drawetS ,esproc sseldaeh eht ta ecnalg tsal a htiW
eid ro ,evil dna ti tpeccA
.kool resolc a teg ot tlenk
,denifnoc yllausu si ecneloiV
.dekcatta gnieb naht
eht dna ,ykculnu eht ,yrawnu eht
.llet t’ndluoc uoy
.oehT ,sdnah ym no esproc a tog I“
,senob s’tac eht fo ffo ylesool gnuh niks ehT
.thgin looc eht otni tuo deppets dna rood eht denepo oehT neht dnA ”.ees I“
,tor ekil saw llems ehT
.tekcaj rebmob tneicna sih ni
.gnol oot raf rof no deggard dah ecnelis eht taht erawa
.detcartsid enot sih ,deilper oehT
revihs drawetS edam taht taef taht t’nsaw ti tuB
,detuohs oehT ”!divaD“
.dnabsuh s’reed eht fo ecnedive rof sotohp eht gninnacs ,dias drawetS
,god.ecioveht ta
,epacse erif eht otno tuo dna wodniw eht hguorht dehsarc eH
.flesti gnidliub eht sa gnilbmurc dna dlo sa roloc tcnitsidni emos fo teprac a dna
,cillatem gnihtemos fo hsalf a thguac thgilnep elttil eht morf maeb ehT ”?evitceteD“
,gniliec eht neve
.evots eht tsap ees ot kcen sih denarc drawetS ,dnah sih htiw eson sih gnirevoC
etarapes os ton era sdlrowrednu owt
,reilrae yrutnec a ,tliub neeb dah yawbus eht nehW
,orajnamiliK dna urulU fo tnorf ni
teerts dedworc a nwod deklaw dah drawetS
.hcuoc eht sdrawot gnilbmut mih tnes dna kcab eht ni mih thguac gniws dnoces A
,tnemom a rof oehT ta detniuqs drawetS
syella krad ni gnittis devlovni ylegral taht reerac a morf detluser
,edis eht ot ylthgils dekcoc daeh
.sitrom rogir ni desnet sdnah eht
”…tpecca ot em tcepxe tsuj t’nac uoY“
,dik a neeb dah drawetS nehw ,ytic eht fo nrutnwod cimonoce lareneg ehT
,sroolf nedoow sseltops s’ronam eht tsniaga wap a deffucs eH
”,tey ton ,erus ton m’I“
eulc a ekil skool sihT
.sllaw eht otno marc dluoc ehs erom tol a erew ereht tnaem tsuj taht tub
.epacse erif eht tuoba ees ot gniog saw I os
.yawrood nepo eht dellif epahs kcalb ,egral a sa
.deggurhs drawetS ”,llew ,haeY“
,levart deyojne evah ot demees reed ehT
,dnim sih ni derepsihw eciov krad emos
.tnemtrapa eht ot noitnetta llac ot gnihtyna detnaw t’ndah rellik eht ebyaM
.yawllah trohs eht otni dna
,flow eht desaeler eH
”?doolb llems uoy naC“
,dias drawetS ”,ythgimla doG“
,citamotua ,suoicsnocnu
saw I“ .tsefas eht t’nsaw osla ti tub ,doohrobhgien suoregnad tsom eht neeb evah ton thgim tI
.rennid tuo ekat ysaerg emos fo stnanmer eht ni neddih-flah
”.doolb fo tol a saw erehT“
,htlif detsurcne dna hsart gniyaced fo amsaim knar eht dnoyeB
”,loof uoy ,nwod
,deirram ton s’ehs esuaceB“
,pu flesmih gniggard saw oehT
,gniddeb kcils-rohci eht ni esahcrup dnif ot elbanu ,steehsdeb eht ta delbbarcs swalc siH
.tekcaj sih fo slepal eht no sdnah
kciht tlef ydob sih tub
,meht fo owt eht dna retal ruoh nA
”,G tnemtrapa s’tI“
”.gnimlehwrevo tsomla si hsart eht tuB .I od rehtieN“
.doolb yna tnecs t’ndluoc eh ,dellik neeb dah ehs erehw edistuo tsuj neve tub ylpeed delahni drawetS
ti denil taht sgnidliub tnemtrapa tneicna ehT
.tnemtrapa eht otni dils oehT sa dessih drawetS ”?lleh eht tahW“
,tecuaf ykael a ekil
,mih nwohs dah tneilc eht etacifitrec egairram eht morf nwonk dah eh tcaf a
.ecnarbmemer ni derevihs eH
”…saw egamad ehT .haey ,tuo sraluconib eht tog I ecnO“
,prahs erew seye siH
.serutcip eht hguorht gnikool tpek eH
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.edisni teg ot tnaw I“
.bmaj nekorb eht tsniaga thguac tub ,derettalc rood ehT
.dworc a ni tuo kcits t’ndid ruf yarg-etals sih dna
.ria eht ta ffins evitatnet a koot neht
.epacse erif eht ot teg ot thguoht ylno sih
.eveels sih fo kcab eht no eson sih debbur drawetS
,krow eye etavirp fo sraey ytnewt ylraen nI
,yawllah eht fo dne eht ta paeh nekorb a otni nwod delbmut oehT sa ,yawa kool ot elbanu ,dehctaw drawetS
.elbissop sa teiuq sa peek ot gniyrt ,ylwols gnivom
,tuo knuks eht gninut ,neht dna
.tsrow eht saw taht ecnelis eht saw ti tuB
.ti no regnif sih tup t’ndluoc eh tub ,ffo dellems gnihtemoS
”…dna reh dniheb pu kcuns enoemoS
,ettenoiram a ekil ,yldrawkwa devom tI
.dehsinav yltnerappa hself eht fo lla
,wonk t’ndid uoy fi tub
,dewollof drawetS ,htaerb sih rednu gnisuorG
.derepsihw drawetS ”?oehT“
,gnineppah saw tahw dootsrednu drawetS erofeb dna
sti si erehw ,oehT ,doG ?ti ot deneppah tahW“
.nosrep gnitivninu na rof
.derab llits hteet sih ,dias oehT ”,oN“
,seY“ ”?yllaer ,cigaM“
.niaga dekconk eh ,ecnelis s’tnemom a retfA .dekconk drawetS
elzzum sih dnuora raeppa ot gnitrats erew taht etihw fo skaerts eht wohs ti did ,rettam taht rof ,roN
.revihs rehtona desserppus flow eht dna mih ta decnalg knuks ehT ”.ti htrow s’tI“
.tesolc ruoy ni gnikrul retsnom elbirroh a t’nsi ylbaborp ohw
,syad wef tsap eht ni tsap derednaw dah ohw
”?em ot gninetsil uoy erA“
,llawyrd eht otni yltcerid devrac
,dednettanu dna dekcolnu ti tfel evah t’ndluow drawetS elihw dna
,noitseuq s’oehT derewsna drawetS ”,haeY“
”,erus ton ma I“ ”?daeh
,emit siht ,yleruS
.detseggus eh ”?tilps revol reH“
.nepo gnuws rood eht dna ekorb bmaj eht sa kcarc elbirroh a saw erehT
,deb eht tsniaga evohs ot
,dnuora denrut I nehw dna
.gnisir regna nwo sih ,dias drawetS
.sesnes sih fo lla gnispilce ssenkrad gnirehtoms
”.deid ehs nehw diarfa t’nsaw ehs taht uoy gnillet saw I
,llef dnah s’gniht-tac ehT
,yawllah eht ni yreppoc gnihtemos fo ffihw a thguac uoy ebyaM
.ylerus ,dedlofnu dah taht stneve ydoolb eht ot seulc yltsahg eb lliw erehT .nialp dna egral tirw eb lliw ecneloiv eht
”.ytilibissop A“
”?ecivda ym erongi ot gniog tsuj er’uoy fi pleh ym rof gniksa rehtob yhW“
llik lliw yeht dna
.llaw raf eht dna evots eht neewteb neddih-flah
.ria eht gnitset dna
.yawa denrut neht ,tnemom a rof deb eht no esproc sseldaeh eht deye eH .knuks eht dias
”.doolb eht ni s’tI“
,yawllah eht sdrawot dereggats flah ,nar flah dna
.yaw eht dael ot knuks eht tsap gnizeeuqs ,dias drawetS
.amora tnasaelp sti rof nwonk neeb reven dah flesti hcihw
.roolf htxis eht ot pu rotavele eht koot oehT dna drawetS
.hcter ot egru eht kcab gnithgif
.meht dniheb desolc rood eht gnivohs
”?ecilop eht dellac uoY“
.tneps ygrene sih fo tsal eht
,haeY“ ”?namow daed ehT“
.tnemom eht ta knuks eht hsup ot detnaw yllaer eh hcum woh erusnu saw eh tub
ylisae dna flow eht naht retrohs toof lluf a saw
.gnivaw yllausu ,yldaorb gninnirg syawla ,otohp hcae ni tneserp dna tnorf saw reed ehT
.ylmrif erom neve rood eht gnidnib ,gut hcae htiw gnitfihs ti leef dluoc eH
.oehT gnigdelwonkca neve reven dna
;tnaig a saw drawetS taht toN
,drawetS ,dlrow ym ni evivrus ot tnaw uoY .netsil uoY“
,edisni tnew yehT
.tnemtrapa eht ta pu gnirats ,dias oehT ”,niaga em lleT“
taht tcaf eht morf edisa yllohw si taht dnA
.niats nworb niht a htiw detaoc saw os ro hcni tsal ehT
,yawrood eht dellif epahs kcalb dnoces a sa ylknalb erats ylno dluoc eH
,roolf eht tih eh nehw dnuorg eht fo ffo decnuob daeh sih dna
,ssenkrad ni deduorhs saw knuks ehT
.evisnefed elttil a ,dias drawetS
.roolf htxis eht ta pu detniop eH
”.evirra ecilop eht erofeb evael dluohs eW
,teef sih peek ot deganam drawetS
,oot ,derevoc saw nib ehT
,sotohp ni derevoc erew yawllah eht fo sllaw ehT
tol a ton s’erehT“
,gnihton dias oehT dnA
,dik htog elttil ynwarcs a ,knuks ehT
,selgna dna stniop prahs lla saw tI .ezingocer t’ndid eh
,oykoT gnikoolrevo
,enohp sih htiw erutcip a deppans eH
”.siht ees dluohs yllaer uoy dnA .sselehtreveN“
.dloh ot elba eb dluohs nosrep elgnis a thguoht eh naht eroM
,lian gnol a saw tI
.retsaot eht ot txen bmurc a sa hcum os tuohtiw
”.ereht pu yaw dellik saw ehs ,gnol taht dnuora kcuts raef fo llems eht fi nevE“
.euqitna na ton yletinifed
htob gnirrefer ,noisserpxe hguone nommoC
,naelc erew sretnuoc eht tub
.riaffa eht rof ecalp a evah ot ti tog ehs ylbaborp ,shtnom fo elpuoc a ereht neeb s’ehs yas sdrocer ,tnemtrapa reh s’tahT“
.retaw seye sih edam ti taht esnetni os egabrag eht fo llems dicnar eht
,nehctik eht ta desuap eH
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
,ffo deneerac dna emarf rood moordeb eht otni dehsarc eH .kcab
,reh deknaht eh nehw flow eht ta detnurg ehS
.ecnatsid gninevretni eht hguorht evom mih nees t’ndah drawetS
.esle enoyna htiw reven dnA
,yadhtrib a derahs ehs dna eH ”!erauqS semiT
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ffuts koob-yrevocsid-fo-yenruoj ,pleh-fles laer saw tI
,trocsE dlo raey neetfif s’drawetS ni
,boj suoromalg a t’nsaw tI
.noitrexe fo tnih tsethgils eht tuohtiw dnuorg eht fo ffo ylidob flow tesyvaeh eht gnitfil ,delworg oehT
ni yltnecer tsom saw krow s’.S.J
.meht ot kool lufnruom ,nrolrof a dah
doolb fo elddup a dna
.teef sih ot kcab ylsuorednop gnibmilc ,desuorg drawetS
.sburhs daed dna sdeew htiw nurrevo saw edistuo eht ,ronam eht fo roiretni enitsirp eht ekilnU
,deid reed ruoy ekil
.ylthgils gnixelf erew swalc eht hguoht sa raeppa ti edam thgil eht fo kcirt emoS
,nees dah drawetS hteet s’rotaderp yna naht
,hteet sih fo thgis ehT
.ereh nrael ot erom s’ereht kniht t’nod I tuB“
.gnihton did siht tub ,rood eht otni redluohs sih gnimmals detrats eh ,cinap a nI
?sruoh eerht naht ssel ni tfel dna
,ereht tuo dial uaelbat eht was dna rood moordeb nepo eht dehcaer eh sa spil sih no deid noitseuq s’drawetS
reprahs dna regnol
,dlom fo reyal ymils ,niht a ni derevoc saw knis eht ni gnittis retaw ehT
.rotarteprep eht fo ecnedive rof gnikool ,teerts eht nacs ot ffo deklats dna niaga erows neht
,s’ti erus ekam ,foor etisoppo eht no pu teg dluoc I fi ees ot gniog saw I“
,thgir saw oehT
.tekcaj tius evisnepxe sih no sdnah sih gnipiw fo wohs a edam neht
enecs emirc a dnuora aera eht ,gnihsalf sthgil dna gniralb sneris htiw pu dewohs ecilop eht litnu taht
”.em morf doolb edih t’nac uoy dnA
,laer era sretsnom dna cigam
.dworc a ni tuo kcuts ohw eno eht ,eno ddo eht saw ,nevig-eman-tsal-on oehT ,knuks ehT
,yksir eb dluoc boj sih ,erofeb snoitautis ni neeb dah eH
,sknalp yrrehc dehsilop eht ot sehctarcs fo elpuoc rehtona gnidda swalc sih
,kcen ro daeh a tuohtiw tub
.teerts eht ssorca yella na ta tniop ot dnah sih derewol drawetS
yawllah egieb a gnilaever
demotsucca era—nevig eman tsal on—oehT dna ,trawetS divaD htoB
.rethgil sdnuop ytfif dna derdnuh a
.yawa raf yrev neeb t’ndah eh—
.moordeb eht morf yawllah eht nwod gnilggurts
”.nees reve evah I cigam luof tsom eht yb detniat si ti
.klawedis nwerts-hsibbur eht nacs ot tuo thgilnep elttil sih dellup eh nehw neve
er’uoY“ ”.gniliar eht revo tneb ,reh ees dluoc I
,deganam eh dna ,taorht sih tuo raet ot ydaer
.ecneloiv fo uaelbat a mih ot laever dna nepo ot rotavele eht rof
,raja saw rood a ebyam
”,evitceted ,srovaf no timil ruoy ot esolc ylsuolirep gninnur era uoY“
.oehT morf ekiledit
.meht fo owt eht neewteb
.elttar ot semarf erutcip eht esuac ot hguone drah
”…tsuj s’ti ,netsiL“
,enrohtwaH .S.J yb ”thgiS ehT“
,ytic eht naht esrow hcum ,luof dnoyeb saw yella ehT
.nwod rac a tif ot worran oot tsomla saw tI
,knuks eht ta derats drawetS ”?tahW“
”,taht tpecca ot uoy tcepxe od I dna nac I“
.ecalp otni ti taes ot rood eht ecrof ot dah eh dna ,thguac bmaj nekorb ehT
debbe evah ot demees regna eht tub ,yliraw knuks eht deye eH
”,nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI“
”,tnemtrapa thgir eht s’ti wonk I“
epahs namuhni ,elbirroh a otni gnihsarc erofeb rulb emorhconom a naht erom ylerab
.rethgirb elttil a dewolg seye s’knuks eht erows drawetS
”thgiS ehT“   yojne esaelP
.delrans oehT ”,yllaer
,enrohtwaH .S.J yb ”thgiS ehT“
.lian eht pu kcip ot eussit a ekil meht desu tub—
.mlac elbirret a htiw ,dias oehT ”,divaD ,nuR“
,raor dna lrans dluow emoceb dah tac eht ekil retsnom a taht detcepxe evah dluow drawetS
”.knis eht ni sehsid eht ni dlom saw ereht tub ,sseltops saw retnuoc ehT“
”?oehT ,no gniog s’lleh eht tahW“
”.knis eht ytpme ro hsart gnittor eht tuo ekat t’ndid tub“ ,deerga oehT
llams detnirp serutcip eht dah dah ehs dna ,rehpargotohp lanoisseforp a neeb t’ndah reed ehT .seifles yltsom
”.doolb llems t’nod I ,on …I“
.yvaeh dna egral gnihtemos deggard dah enoemos erehw doow eht ni hctarcs peed a ot txen thgir
,snap dna stop gnikaos htiw dellif knis sti
.htaed reh ni detluser dah taht egamad fo dnik eht
.taht ekil tuo nettirw ti ees ot driew tlef llits ti tub
.yrruh a ni erew yeht ,pu siht deraelc reveohW .doolb fo
,riats nekorb a dediova evah dluow yeht sa mih diova ybsressap nees dna oehT htiw
,yarg fo taoc kciht a ylsuoiverp ,ruf ehT
,loof a gnieb enod etiuq era uoy fi ,woN“
.nehctik eht otni og ot ytinutroppo eht dah reven dah dna
.yawdaorB dna evA madretsmA neewteb kcolb eht nwod yawflah ,flesti yawyella na naht erom ylerab ,daor elttil ddo na saw tI
.sthguoht sih fo sdaerht eht gniwollof ,ylwols dias eh