weN' .dias eh '!taht no
,erohs ot lamina sselpleh eht delleporp ,dniheb gnimmiws
tahW'   .oga syad ynam os demees won hcihw
;retaw gninnur fo yoj eht otni deretne dna ,wor ot dna
,niaga yrd dna mraw er'uoy llit
,tub ;yaw lausu eht ni
.devresbo ton dah eloM eht hcihw
emit tnatsid taht ecnis laed taerg yrev a hguorht neeb dah eh dna
'?gninaelc-gnirps gnaH' osla dna
gnihgual yltnedive saw eh dna ,taR eht saw tI
'!revo su evah ll'uoY !ti od t'nac uoY' .taob eht fo mottob eht morf ,taR eht deirc
'?niaga dooW dliW eht dnoyeb
etelpmoc saw ssenippah sih thguoht eH
s'erehT'   .ytisoiruc htiw gnilggirw ,eloM eht deksa
'!wolb O' dna '!rehtoB' dias
.snezitic ysub eseht lla gnoma god eldi ylno eht eb ot
tnemom txen eht dna
,tae ot doof hserf dnif dna
,hgual a htiw meht gnivael dna elgrug a htiw sgniht gnippirg
,O'   .taert eht rof regae yllufthgirf saw eh fi sa kaeps ton did eH
,thgilnus eht dna sdnuos eht dna
,sdneirf wen htiw ,erus m’I ,duorp
sihT'   '?yttaR ,em etivni uoy t'ndid
toN' .elims a htiw daeh sih koohs taR ehT
niaga degoorcs eh neht dna
eht tuB .eloM ot noitnetta hcum gniyap ton dna
,od lliw elpoep sa
,ti dnuor pu worg ot yllaudarg nageb ecaf llams a dna
',oot ,wollef doog a
'?sraggeb
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
?tahT'   .revir eht fo edis eno no swodaem—
sa,etal oot hcum neht saw ti ,esruoc fo
',dneirf gnuoy ym ,tey
.ylper yrotcafsitas ylhguoroht a fo kniht dluoc yeht erofeb enog saw dna
.revir eht ni gnilggurts flesmih dnuof eh dna
.owt ro etunim a rof teiuq saw eloM ehT
selttob drah gnulf taht sremaets dna
hcae ta dekool slamina owt ehT   '!gnihtyreve wen ,sgot wen ;taob-regaw wen-dnarb sih nI' .rettO eht deilper ',eno rof ,tuo s'daoT'   '?revir eht no tuo s'ohw ,su llet ,lleW
O' ,psag dna swaperof htob pu dloh ylno dluoc eloM eht taht lufituaeb yrev os saw tI
,tsoh etaredisnoc sih yb sriatspu detrocse eb ot dah eloM ypeels ylbirret a sdrawretfa yltrohs yrev tub
?repeek-kcol eht dna daoT tuoba yrots doog taht uoy llet reve I
,dellud tahwemos saw regnuh rieht fo egde eht nehw
,erom ecno trats a rof ydaer saw lla nehW
oD' .niaga sllucs eht ot koot dna ffo devohs taR eht sa ,eh dias
dloH'   .edis rehtruf eht no egdeh eht dehcaer eh llit wodaem eht ssorca yaw sih deusrup eh
,hsiruolf a htiw kcab sllucs sih gnulf eloM ehT
,mid dna eulb lla s'ti erehW' :deksa eh
.lla ta esnes yna tog ev'uoy fi ,rehtie uoy ron
,sniard nwod serutnevda tuoba dna
epor a denetsafnu dna depeets tub
,nopu gniretne saw eh efil wen eht ni debrosbA
,sriahc dna spets dna sreddal no neht ;sretsud htiw neht ,smoorb htiw tsriF
ta' ,eloM eht dias ',gnikool ma
,taR fo suolaej erom dna erom leef ot nageb eh tuB
sihT'   .taeb laer a fo nrets eht ni detaes yllautca flesmih dnuof
.slavretni ta ti fo tuo yllufreehc pu gnikaeps seciov raelc elttil htiw tey
gniyojne no tneb saw eloM eht tuB .si reven tI
.ylneddus eloM eht deirc
,doom ymaerd a ni sdrawemoh yltneg dellucs taR eht sa wol gnitteg saw nus noonretfa ehT
s'tI' .ylsuoires taR eht deriuqne
,revir eht ssorca dekool dna
I'   .elttil a htolc-elbat eht ffo rednaw ot elba erew seye s'eloM eht dna
,neht ,rednow llams saw tI
.esruoc fo ,regdaB s'ereht neht dnA
.mih htiw serefretni ydoboN
.em ot wen os si siht lla tub
.taR etartsorp eht fo pot eht no gniyl flesmih dnuof eh dna ,daeh sih evoba pu welf sgel sih
egde eht yb doots eh ylneddus
.taR eht detuohs '!regdaB dlo ,no emoC'   .meht
tel' ,taR eht deilper ',ll—e—
.sesu sti dnatsrednu ylluf tey ton did eh hguoht neve
.regdaB htiw dleif-a raf snoisrucxe ro
.efil gniees seilf-yaM fo sdoolb gnuoy yb detceffa noihsaf detacixotni eht ni tnerruc eht trawhta ylidaetsnu devrews ylf-yaM tnarre nA   '.…daoT
.noziroh tnatsid eht sa raf sa
,snoihsuc eht deyevrus dna
,eloM lamsid eht oS
;mih rewsna ot eciov on dnif dluoc eh taht
;seirots gniticxe yb dnuob-lleps eno sdloh ohw nam a fo edis eht yb
tuB' :ylevitcelfer rettO eht dekramer
,ssenippah reehs morf seot sih delggaw eloM ehT
'!taob a ni yllaicepse—
ot elba neve saw eh dna ,niaga deviver
,ruf kcalb sih revo lla hsaw-etihw fo sehsalps dna ,seye dna taorht sih ni tsud dah eh llit
nrut sti ni pu dleh taht
,ylhsittep rehtar ,eloM eht dias ',klat ot llew yrev lla sti
,enut a demmuh taR ehT
reveN' :dehtuom—nepo ,taR eht deirc
,knab eht fo egde eht evoba flesti dewohs
.ti fo edam eh ssem ecin a dna ,yad yreve dna yad lla tnup ot tub
fO'   .niaga nwod gnittis ,taR eht dias
stnecs eht ,elppir eht
,serutnevda taerg dna
potS'   .ecnedifnoc eritne htiw sllucs eht debbarg dna
'?enif si sihT'   .wodaem taerg a fo
.rettO eht saw rehtieN
,ylisub delbmar eh swodaem eht hguorht rehtiht dna rehtiH
evarg A   .sreksihw htiw
,ydaer saw lla nehW
.gnivom eb ot thguo ew esoppus I' ,taR eht dias ',llew
hcuS'   '.hserf gnihtemos no strats dna
,knird dna doof dna
,esle erehwemos hcaer uoy rehtehw ro
,taR eht dias '!ohO
,ti fo tnorf ni riahc-mra na ni eloM eht detnalp dna
.yaw fo tros gnitivni na ni ylireehc depurrihc dna
,sespoc eht ssorca ,sworegdeh eht gnola
,rehtegotla ecafrus eht dessim eH
no htrof dereep
.teksab-noehcnul lufituaeb taht tsol evah thgim I woh kniht I nehw em sliaf etiuq traeh yM
,rettam t'nseod taht gnihtemos s'taht dnA' .taR eht dias
nehT' .taR eht
.raf os seirots derdnuh a rof ediserif eht ta ynapmoc em gnipeek rof uoy knahT
;laem lufreehc tsom a saw reppuS
,emaharG htenneK yb
.no os dna—sexof dna—staots dna—
gniod htrow hcum os flah—
a ni neeb
,woN' ,dias taR eht
gnikcirp ecneicsnoc ysaenu na gnivah fo daetsni dnA .deipucco dna
.ti wonk I dna ,ssa etelpmoc a
',staob htiw ro—staob ni tuoba—
,dna ;ti tuoba erom yna kniht uoy t'noD
,rettO htiw sgnihsif-thgin dna
.eurt eb ot doog oot demees lla tI
,evoba eloh sih otni pu debmilc
;noitautis ylekilnu na hcus ni rats a eb yldrah dluoc ti tuB
,worrub eht fo tuo-gnimoc s’elom detartsurf a tuoba si
'!gnihsawetihw naht retteb si
,mih fo tuo tew eht fo emos gnurw dna ,tib a nwod mih debbur dah taR eht nehW
,gnihton dias taR ehT
',dlroW ediW eht semoc
elzzum gninetsilg daorb A
a fi sa—gnihtemos od ot uoy gnitnaw syawla dna gnol yad lla tuoba meht fo lla ,snehroom ,skcihcbad ,srehsif—gnik ,srettO
yeht tub—taht lla dna ,teem ew nehw yad fo emit eht ssap—
naeL' .nwod ylregnig deppets eloM eht sa waperof sih pu dleh eh nehT
'?ereht revo seil
:sediseb sseltser tib a gnitteg saw dna )thguoht eh os(
l1'eH'   .krow sih ot ylnrets delttes dna daeh sih koohs—
,llew—ot esle eno
!dloheb ,lla fo tsal dna
,worb detaeh sih desserac sezeerb tfos
'!taR ,daeha kooL'   '——gnissem
,esuoh-llim delbag—yerg a
erofeb revir a nees eh dah efil sih ni reveN
,dlrow eht ni seirots tseb
,gninrom eht lla drah yrev gnikrow neeb dah eloM EHT
,eye sih thguac ,egde s'retaw eht evoba tsuj
erehwyreve gnidnif
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
!yteicoS setah
,tnemtnetnoc lluf fo hgis a htiw tsehc sih daerps
?selbbuB'   '.ynnuf sa em sekirts taht gniht a si tahT
,nac uoy sa drah sa htap-gniwot eht nwod dna pu torT
mih esaelp dluow gnihtoN
;flesmih yb lla ti kcapnu ot dewolla eb ot ruovaf a sa deggeb eloM ehT
'?ylevil pets ,neht
,ylyhs eloM eht deksa
saw ti ylloj woh leef ylno dluoc
taht em gnillet syawla era slamina rehto eht dna
railimaf eht dnoyeb og ot gnirad
gnirepsihw dna mih
pU' ,flesmih ot gnirettum dna swap elttil sih htiw ylisub gnikrow ,deparcs dna dehctarcs dna delbbarcs dna
.tnacav ylraelc saw delwarps dah eh noerehw frut eht tub
s'tahT'   '?erofeb sa no og sgniht tel dna
dias gnilias tub gnihton saw ti ,ecnO'   .dehgual ti dna rehto
,oot ,erew yeht seirots gnillirht yreV
s'tahW'   .niaga sllucs eht koot dna
ytilibats on
tuo flesmih deluah rettO eht dna
,llits ;tey taht nees t'nevah uoy tub—
.retaw eht ta gid taerg a edam dna
retniap eht deitnu eh nehT
'!won ,wor ot tnaw I ,esaelP
,gnilkcuhc dna gnisahc
.elbbub dna rettahc
!nwod ,nwod ,nwod tnew eh sa srae sih ni gnas ti woH
,ecaep s'tnemom a teg dna yrt ot retawkcab siht pu emac I
ecnepxiS' .pag eht ta tibbar ylredle na dias '!pu
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.niaga dleh dna thguac erew dna
,lleW' '——— mih llet uoy t'ndid yhW
I'   .mih brutsid ot eroberof dna
revihs-a dna ekahs-a saw llA
,miws ot dna ,wor ot uoy hcaet ll'I dnA
eveileB' .ekorts sih rof drawrof tnael eh sa
;meht yb ylbamuserp os ,sremaets morf dna ,gnulf ylniatrec erew selttob tsael ta—
,evissergorp dna ,yppah
.staob ni tuoba gnissem ylpmis sa
eh saw ti rof—daoT tub
.gnihsaw )yllarutan( dna
.teksab-noehcnul eht tuo gnuws dna
.wonk t'nod uoy esruoc fo dna ,ti ot wen
s'tahW' .ylireehc taR eht dednopser
evohS'   .teksab-noehcnul rekciw
,ylnmelos taR retaW eht dias
!ym O' ,gnipsag llits
,nees eb ot rettO na toN
sI'   '?neht ,gniod neeb uoy evah I tahw—
yawa spord lla ti nehw
,nmutua ro gnirps ,remmus ro retniw ni rehtehW
'!enif yrev ti tuc dna tsaeb naem a m'I
.tcudnoc lufetargnu dna hsiloof ym rof deedni yrros yrev ma I
llA' .rettO eht deunitnoc '!erehwyreve supmur a
,eciov wol a ni dias eh
eW' .yltrohs taR eht dias
noitanitsed ruoy ta evirra uoy rehtehw
,lla ta erehwyna teg reven uoy rehtehw ro
wollip sih no daeh sih dial noos eh erehw
diD' .rettO eht delkcuhc
.ti od ot mih diap uoy fi ,rehtie ,esle erehwyna evil t'ndluow
;taob eht fo nrets eht ni taes sih koot ,detcejed dna pmil ,eloM eht
,gnihgual mih leef dluoc eloM eht—
tnemmoc fo tros yna edabrof etteuqite-lamina taht detcellocer eloM eht dna
.taoc sih no tup ot gnitiaw neve tuohtiw esuoh eht fo tuo detlob dna
',dooW dliW eht tsuj s'taht ,O
taht dnaldoow fo dnuorgkcab a sdrawot wap a gnivaw ,eloM eht deksa
yeht sa stibbar rehto eht gniffahc
esuoh elttil ylwol dna krad sih neve gnitartenep
',pahc dlo ,yllufwa sehtolc ruoy ekil
;ti fo traeh eht ni thgir 'sevil eH
.aes elbaitasni eht ot
.revir def-lluf a fo
.tlit lluf knab eht kcurts taob ehT .etal oot saw tI
,mih deliah dna
gnihton etulosba—
'?taht lla sa ecin os ti
.yresim fo pmul yplup ,yhsauqs a
!swollef uoy nopu elbmuts neht dna
.llew sa tib yreve ti od dluoc eh taht repsihw ot nageb edirp sih dna
',uoy no drah eb t'ntsum I
,gniog reven m'I dna
:laiceps gnihtemos si yrots s’yadot ,edosipe htderdnuh eno ruo etarbelec ot dna
,moordeb tseb eht ot
.gnikrow ysub swollef rehto eht lla ees ot sa
,taob—esuoh sih ni mih htiw yats dna og ot dah lla ew dna
taes sih ni kcab tnael eh sa ti eveileb ot deraperp etiuq saw eh hguoht
degoorcs dna delbbarcs dna
,no os dna '———mih dednimer evah thgim uoY' '———
',lliw eh esruoc
;staob—ni—tuoba—gnissem' :ylimaerd no tnew eh ',gnissem ylpmiS
'.skool ti sa ysae os ton s'tI
htrae eht fo traeh eht morf tnes
,ti dniheb sredluohs hgih htiw ,daeh ypirts a dna
er'uoY' .ecnaraebrof htiw taR eht dias
.repmet fo ssol hcum tuohtiw ,tsal ta dehsinif tog gniht eht ,wohemos ,llits—
.goD fo ecioV ehT eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
;hsawetihw fo liap a dna hsurb a htiw
,elkraps eht htiw detacixotni
;slamina owt rof ezis eht tsuj saw dna
!gnirettulps dna gnihguoc
,olluH'   .taR retaW eht dias '!eloM
,ssarg eht morf mih ta pu gnirats etalp a was eh
niaga ro ;wodniw moordeb tseb ym yb snur retaw nworb eht dna
'.teksab-noehcnul eht rof evid I elihw
,ynapmoc dna ,stnua dna ,em ot retsis dna rehtorb
.ecnaraeppa delggardeb sih tuoba rehto hcae ot gnireggins erew ohw snehroom fo elpuoc a ot klat-kcab thgiarts emos evig
sihT' .flesmih ot dias eh
.eloM ekil lamina gnillewd-htrae na ot
'?teksab-noehcnul eht kcap retteb dah su fo hcihw rednow I
,ffo tes yeht sa dna
,gnola ylisae os dna ylgnorts os gnillucs
:rehtegotla yawa gnivom era elpoep ynam taht syadawon dedworc os si knab ehT
,ecno ta ti ot tuo tnew traeh elohw s'eloM eht dna
.eciton sih detcartta tsrif dah taht
dnA'   .tcejbus eht deppord eh os
!era uoy diputs
.wodniw sih fo llis eht gnippal saw reviR eht
',nodrap ruoy geb
.tsaf edam dna ssorca yltrams dellucs taR ehT
'!ssa yllis uoy ,ti
ti fo deb eht fo tsom revo dohs yrd tuoba rettop nac I dna
ylthgit pu depparts dna dekcap teksab eht tog dah eh nehw tsuj hguohtla dna ,gnihtyreve
,yttaR'   ,noitome htiw nekorb
.yad-ot revir eht no tuo smees dlrow eht
,emas eht lla s'tI
'!gnivah m'I yad a
dooW dliW eht
,ti daerps dna htolc—elbat eht tuo koohs dneirf deticxe sih elihw ,tser dna
,nees evah ot thguo ydobyna hcihw krof a tuo detniop taR eht niaga enod neeb dah boj eht nehw dna
'!poolc' a dna retaw fo lriws A
.drawno devom remmus gninepir eht sa tseretni fo lluf dna
taob a ni emoh ta etiuq ydaerla dna
,yldesopmoc no tnew taR eht
,yrehtoms dna llud
.erutcip a dnuor emarf a ekil
,ecno ta sgel ruof sih lla ffo gnipmuj
,leehw-llim gnippird sseltser a htiw mra-ni-mra
no ylidaets dellucs ,saw eh wollef elttil doog eht ekil ,taR retaW ehT
nI' .hgual tnasaelp a htiw pu flesmih gnikcip
wohemos eh '!hsawetihw'
'?ereht ni elpoep ecin yrev yeht t'nera—
ton saw teksab eht gnikcaP
gnikaeps fo rennam dnik sih yb dehcuot os saw eloM ehT
tuB'   '!staob fo tuo deppord evah elpoep sselerac sgniht dna
!yttaR' ,dias eh yltneserp dna
dnoyeB'   '?tfird duolc ylno ti si ro ,snwot fo ekoms eht ekil gnihtemos dna
'gniht ylno eht s'tI
fo I retpahC saw sihT
.mih tel taR eht ,esruoc fo ,oS .eloM eht dias ',em tel esaelp
'?os kniht yllaer uoy
yeht t'nerA'   '.sreknab—revir ew ,hcum yrev ereht og t'nod
,tsaf reh edam dna
.rats ynit a ekil erom ecno delkniwt neht ,dehsinav
',teef ruoy rednu taht
regnol meht fo hcae
"swolliW eht ni dniW ehT" fo I retpahC
,em ot doog on s'taht knird htiw gnimmirb era tnemesab dna srallec ym dna
,etisoppo knab eht ni eloh krad a
.ekal dekcol-dnal elttil a
.syad tsom ti fo tuo naht retaw eht ni erom m'I
meht htiw sdneirf doog yrev m'I—
,weiv otni dehsalf taob-regaw a neht tsuj dna
,eerf sevlesmeht koohs taht setamyalp hserf no flesti gnilf ot
,taob eht tnew revO   !hsoolpS—
.smaerd gnikaw gnol demaerd dna retaw eht ni wap a deliart eh
s'tahT'   .weiv morf deraeppasid dna kcab sih denrut dna ',ynapmoC
,knab eht edisgnola taob eht thguorb taR ehT
retaw eht demarf ylkrad
tib a ti t'nsi
,lriws dna eltsur ,selkraps dna smaelg dna stnilg—
ssarg eht no htgnel lluf ta lwarps ot dna
,ereht neeb reven ev'I
,eloM eht ot devresbo eh
.taob—esuoh a ni efil sih fo tser eht dneps ot gniog saw eH
.syaw sti dna efil edisrevir dna revir a ot wen gnieb eh
,dneirf gnuoy ym ,em
!wollef dlo ,neht ,woN' ,dias eh
.ti dekil ew dneterp dna
.mrow-wolg a rof llams dna gnirettilg oot saw ti dna
,ylgnireej dekramer eh
.ti fo mrahc eht s'taht ,rettam ot yllaer smees gnihtoN
,ysub syawla er'uoy
s'tI' .taR eht dias ',ti ni dna ti no dna ti htiw dna ti
'!si eh wollef fo tros eht tsuj
,wap sih hguorht dna mra sih nwod thgir
,sgnittif gnitanicsaf eht lla dna ,skcolwor eht ,srao eht
.nwod dekool eloM ehT
dneirf dnuof-wen sih taht gniwonk
ti enod ev'uoy nehw dna
taob elttil a otni deppets ylthgil neht ;ti no deluah dna
!m'H' ,detnurg neht ;owt ro ecap a drawrof dettort regdaB ehT
,lleW'   .revetahw nosaer on ro nosaer yna rof ,tnemom yna ta sdneirf s'eno fo ecnaraeppasid neddus eht no
.noitalever hserf hcae ta '!ym O
,t'nyam yeht spahrep ro sllih eb yam tahw sees eno dna
,ti fo derit steg eh
,ti gniyned on s'ereht ,semitemos tuo kaerb
!dneirf suoreneg ym
.kcen sih fo kcab eht yb mih deppirg wap mrif a nehT
,rehtegot revir eht nwod pord ew gnisoppus
,dekool eh sa ,nehT
ereht—esruoc fo ,lleW'   .eloM eht deksa
'.hcnul ot gniog er'ew erehw ,tsal ta retawkcab ruo s'ereH !neht woN
'!uoy sselb ,thgir lla
htiw lamina na rof
ehT'   '!reviR—a—si—siht—oS
'!neht ,etunim a drah
.tsud dna esion morf etomer dna level doolf
,emit dnoces eht rof ria eht ni sgel sih htiw taes sih ffo sdrawkcab llef dna esirprus yb nekat saw
yB' .taR eht denialpxe
.8091 ni dehsilbup tsrif
.gnitnup ot koot dna taht fo derit eh
,gnitaob—esuoh saw ti raey tsaL
.esac eht syawla si
lla ta esuoh s'daoT ekil ton—wonk uoy ,hguor dna nialp yrev s'tI
;pus ro etib rof desuap ton dah dna
tahW' .snoihsuc tfos eht otni yllufssilb kcab denael dna
.ton retteb hcum d'uoy tub ,ekil uoy fi ti od nac uoy dna
ekil thgis tsrif ta demees tahw otni dessap won yeht
'!og ew pU !og ew
,nihtiw demahsa dna tuohtiw tew
.rettam t'nseod ti ,me' fo tuo ro
eht fo noissecorp gnilbbab a
.esaelp ,niaga ti ot refer reve t'noD
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom ynam dnif nac uoY
,gninrom siht dnah no esle gnihton yllaer ev'uoy fI !ereh kooL
,emaharG htenneK yb
eye sti ni elkniwt emas eht htiw ,ecaf dnuor
',riaffa utpmorpmi na saw
,edirp dna ,noitcafsitas-fles dna ,hcnul fo lluf yrev saw eloM
s'eloM eht—sih otni os dna
,mih ta dekniw ti
,em evigrof dna ecno siht ti koolrevo uoy lliW
.tol dexim a era stibbar tub ,me' fo emos—stibbar eht dnA
,tsrif eht ,retpahc sihT
;ot ekops yeht mohw erew yeht ralucitrap woh dna ,snoreh tuoba dna
,seerged yb erohs ot ytreporp gnitaolf sih dehctef
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
gniraeh dellud sih no llef sdrib yppah fo lorac eht
.emoh elttil sih gninaelc-gnirps
'?mih htiw erefretni dluohs ohw
evoba pu gnihtemoS
',ti edisni nekcihc dloc
dehctarcs dna deparcs eh oS
,olluH'   .ylsuoituac rehto hcae dedrager dna doots slamina owt eht nehT
,taob eht fo mottob eht ta kcab sih no yal ,namsrao suoyoj eht ,remaerd ehT
,retaw teiuq eht fo ecafrus eht woleb demaelg stoor-eert ykans nworb
,ruolrap eht ni erif thgirb a edam taR eht
,redro eud ni stnetnoc rieht degnarra dna
yaw a ni thgir lla er'yehT
',taht ekil sllor eh fi etunim a ni taob eht fo tuo eb
ecafrus eht ot esor eh sa dekool nus eht emoclew dna thgirb woH
;ti ot edulla ot neve ro ,daeha elbuort elbissop no llewd ot
etteuqite-lamina tsniaga etiuq si ti taht llew wenk eloM ehT
,eloM detapicname eht rof seno ralimis ynam fo tsrif eht ylno saw yad sihT
yhW' .rednevorp eht rof gnikam ,devresbo eh
W'   .ylsuovren elfirt a ,eloM eht dias
.riah yklis kciht dna srae taen llamS
dellevarg eht ot
,dnuos fo rumrum gnihtoos a htiw ria eht dellif
'?ti fo yad gnol a evah dna
'!daor etavirp eht yb gnissap fo egelivirp eht rof
,taob eht fo edis eht ta barg a edam eh ,demrala yltaerG
.emit-reppus llit seirots revir mih dlot dna
'.su fo yna sa retaw eht no ydnah sa eb noos ll'uoy dna
miws ot tnrael eH
,mih dnuora dna woleb htrae eht ni dna
!pop ,tsal ta llit
gnol os ni devil dah eh egarallec eht fo noisulces eht retfa dna
.detanicsaf ,decnartne
m'I' .dessap dah os ro ruoh na flah emos retfa dekramer eh
.meht gnoma yltnatsnoc os
,eloM suoutpmetnoc dna tneitapmi eht yb tnatsni na ni revo delwob saw eH
,gnola ylsselmia derednaem eh sa ,nehw
,od ot esle gnihtemos syawla s'ereht
'!yad lufrednow a neeb sah
,floWcaM boR yb detceles saw tI
,egats-gnidnal sih ni gnir a hguorht retniap eht depool eH .taR eht dias
gnirepsihw tnew dniw eht tahw fo gnihtemos ,slavretni ta
.yad-ot mih fo erom yna ees t'nahs ew woN
,meht dniheb eltsur a saw erehT
,gninaelc sti tuohtiw gnirps fo thgiled eht dna
;eye na eb ot flesti deralced os dna
ydeerG'   .taoc sih morf retaw eht koohs dna
,flesmih ot sgniht-yrteop erom gniyas dna retaw eht revo tuo gnizag saw ohw
­dloc' ;ylfeirb taR eht deilper
,ylsuoirepmi mih gnillac saw
neeb evah I ,deednI
,sriew tuoba seirotS
dloH'   '!ecno ta trats su teL' .dias eh
,riew a fo elbmut ymaof dna redluohs yrevlis eht
emaharG htenneK yb
!taR retaW eht saw tI
.tlef ti tew yrev woh ,O dna
,dlrow wen lufrednow dna reeuq a otni democlew flesmih dnif ot
.tsedrah sih gnikrow tub ,laed doog a gnillor dna yldab gnihsalps—erugif tuots ,trohs a—rewor eht
ssarg mraw eht ni gnillor flesmih dnuof eh dna
erutpar dna esirprus sih ot eloM eht dna
nodrap geb I—tsael tA—
,mih rof sreppils dna nwog-gnisserd a nwod dehctef gnivah
I'   '.ti droffa nac I sa noos sa ,yad emos flesym tius—gnikoms tevlev kcalb a teg ot gniog
I llew—reven uoy—
.wap sih fo kcab eht htiw owt ro raet a yawa hsurb ot dah eh dna
ecalp sih koot eloM tnahpmuirt eht elihw
,egde rehtie ot nwod depols frut neerG
egdeh eht fo edis eht gnola dettort ohw
.yaw siht deneppah tI
,noitcerid rehtona ni dekool yldnik taR eht tuB
'.tcaf eht s'taht dna
'?tahW'   '.efil ym lla ni erofeb taob a ni neeb reven ev'I ,wonk uoy
,dna mih fo edis rehto eht yb emas eht did eh neht
,llams yrev nehw ,stort eno sa dettort eh revir eht fo edis eht yB
"swolliW eht ni dniW ehT"
hcuS'   .htiwhtrof sdneirf erew slamina owt eht dna
,ruf sih no toh kcurts enihsnus ehT
,gninrom taht I ruoh ylrae yrev a ta gninaelc-gnirps sih detrats dah eh rof ,yebo ot dalg yrev deedni saw eloM eht dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
esac sih ni derewsna hcihw lennut elttil peets eht rof edam eh dna
.emit elttil a rof em htiw pots dna emoc retteb dah uoy kniht yllaer I !ereh kool
.stnemeticxe sti dna nuf sti tog syawla s'ti
'   .ria eht ni sleeh sih
,yltneserp taR eht dias '?ta gnikool uoy era
,dehctiweb saw eloM ehT
ssarg eht no tas eh sA
.ria dna nus eht ot reraen era secnediser esohw slamina yb denwo evird-egairrac
,hO'   .yltneserp taR eht deriuqne
,nihtiw etihw dna edistuo eulb detniap saw tI
,ekac—mulp ekil sllems taht dum fo sehctap swohs dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.ti htiw dnal ot delggurts dna
,thguac eh smets-deer eht ot rae sih htiw dna
,taf a rednu gnireggats deraeppaer lavretni trohs a retfa dna
.smra yraew dna kcab gnihca na dna
'.wonk uoy ,taht naem yltcaxe t'nod I—
.elbatrofmoc uoy ekam nac I
,flesmih ot revo sgniht-yrteop gnirumrum
noinO' .tuoba saw wor eht tahw ees ot seloh rieht morf yldeirruh depeep
,thgilnus eht otni tuo emac tuons sih
tuoba lla s’ti dna
tsuJ' .ksa ot derutnev eloM eht '?semit ta llud
O'   '——retaw ­ados ­edanomel­ reeb­regnig­ taem­ dettop­ sehciwdnas ­sserc­ sllor­ hcnerf­ dalas­ snikrehg ­delkcip ­feeb­ dloc ­mah­ dloc­ eugnot
.gniyas saw eh drow a draeh reven eloM ehT
?taR retaW a ot tew elttil a
gnihton si ereht
eno yb eno stekcap suoiretsym eht lla tuo koot
'?ti edisni
pu doots taR ehT
uoY' .troffe na htiw rehtegot flesmih gnillup ,eloM eht dias
evoba ,ecnediser edisrevir uojib a fo dnof dna stnaw wef
meht fo daeha elihw
?revir eht yb evil yllaer uoy
.tuohs a ekil tsomla
,tnemtnetnoc dna ecaep taerg ni
'?revo emoc ot ekil uoy
,ekip gnipael dna
,yhW'   .yltnacifingis dedda eh ',ton retteb d'yehT
,duorP'   '.eloM .rM dneirf ym—yaw eht
,srae sih ni llits saw eciov ehT
!rehtegot dah ev'ew semit eht !droL
ekam dluow ti ecalp-gnillewd guns ecin a tahw gniredisnoc ot llef eh ylimaerd dna
tsal ta dlot eb ot
.ecruosikiW yb dedivorp txet niamod-cilbup eht dna
,yraurbeF ni no era sdoolf eht nehW
.taob eht otni nwod ti dessap eh sa
,roolf eht no hsurb sih nwod gnulf ylneddus eh taht
stirips s'eloM eht yltneserp dna
ylpmiS' .taR detnioppasid eht devresbo
yas uoy t'ndid yhw
,sdoolf neddus dna
;ralucitrap ni gnihtyna od reven uoy dna
,knab eht no nwod mih tes dna ,tuo mih deluah
,maerts niam eht gnivaeL
,flesruoy gnitser eb ot hcum os ton spahrep si yadiloh a fo trap tseb eht ,lla retfA
:yojne esaelP   .evol
;edur yrev em kniht tsum
.teksab eht gnikcapnu sa krow tnasaelp hcus etiuq
,saw retaw eht dloc woh ,ym O
,rettO eht dias ',erus m'I
'!ym O !ym O !ym
?eciN'   .mih rednu ylthgil yaws taob eht tlef dna
,erohsa ylefas eloM drawkwa llits eht depleh ,tsaf reh edam
,lamina deidob-lluf ,suounis ,keels siht—
.em ro uoy ot rehtie
oD'   '!hcum oot si sihT' :seicatsce ni eloM eht deirc ',pots ,pots
.erom on elbisiv saw ylf-yaM eht dna
.gniwonk htrow ton si wonk t'nseod ti tahw dna
.snossel wef a dah ev'uoy llit tiaw'—dias eh
,yrd ylriaf saw eh llit tuoba dettort
.revir eht fo ecafrus eht no selbbub fo kaerts a saw ereht niaga tuB
ti gniwonk tuohtiw no gnittis neeb dah eh hcihw ,top dratsum eht
,slennahc eht golc deew dna sehsur eht dna
,mih egludni ot desaelp yrev saw taR eht dna
.retaw eht fo ecafrus eht gnola gnillevart ees I taht selbbub fo kaerts a
,kciht gnulc llits fi sevael s'raey tsal nierehw egdeh a morf gnideecorp
.thgir lla era slerriuqs ehT .ees em
'!wollef dlo ,ni hctip
,meht tsurt yllaer t'nac uoy ,llew—neht dna
yB'   '!efil ylloj a tahW
,gnivah htrow ton si tog t'nsah ti tahW
,ecaf elttil nworb A
oN'   '?htiw drow a ssap ot esle eno on dna ,revir eht dna uoy
teksab-noehcnul eht rof yllufsseccus devid yllanif dna
.gnignol dna tnetnocsid enivid fo tirips sti htiw
;mra s'eloM eht rednu ti devohs dna llucs a fo dloh tog taR ehT   .kcen—
.lla ta ,eb ot desu ti tahw t'nsi ti ,on O
evoba ria eht ni gnivom saw gnirpS
,mih ot no derettahc llits revir eht yb elihw
,gniddub srewolf ,gnidliub sdrib
!niaga gniknis flesmih tlef eh nehw riapsed sih saw kcalb woH
;snoisrucxe elttil eseht no ekat syawla I tahw ylno
dnA'   .taR eht detcerroc ',reviR
woH' .rehto hcae ta gnilbmurg detrats lla yeht nehT
tahW'   '!ot dnetta ot nwo sih fo ssenisub on dah wollef
slesaeW'   .yaw fo tros gnitatiseh a ni taR eht denialpxe ',srehto era—
;meht detarapes taht dnalsi eht ssorca maerts niam eht fo espmilg a teg dluoc yeht tas yeht erehw morF
"swolliW eht ni dniW ehT"
;t'nod uoy rehtehw ro ,yawa teg uoy rehtehW
,ti fo traeh eht ni nwod elkniwt ot demees llams dna thgirb gnihtemos ,dezag eh sA
,emoh tog yeht nehW
'?ecuas-noinO !ecuas-
,taR eht taht ,ylneddus os ,sllucs eht dezies dna pu depmuj eH
dluoW'   .eloM eht dias '!taR
reh dethgir ,taob eht derevocer ,niaga retaw eht otni degnulp taR eht elihw
gnivil fo yoj eht ni
;pu sekat eh revetahw
.rehto yna tnaw t'nod I dna ,dlrow ym s'tI
!regdaB dlo raeD
,knab eht no tas eh ,tsal ta derit nehw dna
gnihtyreve—gnitsurht sevael