.thgiltops tnaig a fo syar eht ni thguac erew ehs fi sa enilef gnuoy eht fo ruf dlog eht gnitanimulli
.don a deganam I
,seye ym htiw reh hguorht seloh gninrub ylbaborp saw I
.repeed gud ehs os
,peed a ni koot I sa derewsna ylkciuq I
;dekan leef em edam tI
.ereht neve t’nsaw teprac eht fi sa
.noisiv reh ni reggib dna rethgirb worg
.gniklat eunitnoc ot elba yllanif saw I erofeb
dna nosillA deltrats hcihw ,taes eht ni pmuj em edam tI
,yrolg roirepus rieht lla ni ,sgnieb namuh
.tuhs rood eht gnimmals
,ocsaif gnitsevrah nagro eht fo dne eht drawot dereenigne
.yrtsudni ytilitu eht ni reerac sih no gnisucof elihw
.swodniw tew eht ta kcab gnicnalg erofeb derettum I
.dnopser ot woh fo erusnu
sniev ym hguorht gniwolf retaw eci ekil
,thgin taht snoitidnoc tew eht rof t’nerew ti fi
.em ta erats ot ton gniyrt saw ehs erehw ,edis s’revird eht ot detfihs I
.gnihtemos diova ot gniyrt saw ehs ebyam kniht yeht
ygolohtna eht ni derutaef yllanigiro
gnivird detrats dna
kool uoy esuaceB
noitadipert ym hctam ot demees swodniw ssalg ehT
?sgnul ym pu gnizis uoy erA
”?reH“  ”.reh tsol I nehw
.enim tem seye reh sa
.ylgnilliw os gniod saw I dna-
,tnamrod gniyl saw eh elihw tsaeb eht morf yawa teg ot detnaw I
,deddon yllautneve I tub ,elihw a koot tI
retaw gnidacsac fo stelpord ynit esohT
.rettam t’ndid ti tub ,thguoht eht hsinif t’ndluoc I  ”…ym saw ehs dnA
.ti dniheb rorrim eht gnisopxe ,edis ym no nwod rosiv eht deppilf dna
;reh fo em dednimer yehT
.hguoht kniht ot emit hcum t’nsaw erehT
.ekatsim a saw sihT
delims nosillA tub
elbmur gninefaed a htiw reh decnelis ruopnwod eht tub
.uoy fo namuh …woH
seippup suoremun dna rentrap sih htiw saxeT ni sevil yltnerruc dna
.taes eht ni tfihs ot em gnicrof
.dehcaorppa ew sa reggib gniworg
.resolc deppets I sa retaw fo gnimmurd sseltneler eht yb detluassa gnieb saw cirbaf ehT
.wodniw tnorf s’rac eht tuo gniralg
.retteb ti lortnoc ot woh wenk I hsiw tsuj I
…uoY“  .dluow ydoboN
,tfos reh draeh I erofeb gnol nosillA llems dluoc I
.su drawot yks suorbenet eht hguorht delbmur taht lrans gnirednuht
.dnah ni allerbmu reh htiw yawrood eht ni doots nosillA sa edisni yaw sih pir ot gniyrt lamina dliw a fo swolleb eht ekil erutcurts eht nihtiw gniohce
,yltneloiv os selcsum ym ta deppir sredluohs ym ni msaps eht dna
efil htiw sgnul ym gnillif
derutaef seirots dah osla eH .snikS tnereffiD
”.uoy eracs ot naem t’ndid I“  .htaerb gnihtoos
,niaga ecno tnemevap dilos htiw tcatnoc ni emac elcihev eht nehw dna
.hctiwt tuons ym edam tI
.ti tuoba tnereffid os gnihtemos saw ereht …niar eht tuB
.ot evah ot gniog saw I wenk I
,eye ym fo renroc eht fo tuo em ta kool reh was I
.em htiw pu gnipeek melborp a evah t’ndid nosillA dna ,dluoc I sa tsaf sa rac eht ot nar tsuj I
,semit lareves seye ym knilb ot dah I dna
.em ta ecnalg kciuq a edam ehs sa
.epan ym no pu dnats sriah eht edam taht lworg gnilbmur ,wol a htiw ybbol eht gnillif
,tcapmi nopu detpure yehT
retaw eht otni degnulp ti erofeb nac ados a ekil gnilknirc yllaitrap
.yaw s'mrah ni dna edistuo ydaerla allerbmu reh
.enif eb dluow gnihtyreve dna yawa og
.noitcafsitas eht ti evig t’ndid I
doolb llems dluoc tsaeb eht dna
.gnits seye ym gnikam
feiler fo hgis rehtona dehtaerb I
,dnoces a rof seye ym desolc I
”?rehtaew eht htiw od ot gnihtemos evah ti seoD“
.pots ti tel t’ndluow eH
,tew gnippird saw tuons dna ecaf ym revo lla riah ehT  .yggos dekool I
,em rof tsuj redrah nwod emoc ot dediced dah niar eht fi sa tsomla saw tI
,dnim ym morf dedaf noos mrof laerehte s’ykceB tub ,eman reh tuo dellac tsomla I
.elkcuhc ot nageb
.wodniw eht gnirrulb saw taht retaw fo reyal niht eht htiw pu peek ot gniniarts
,flesym ot ti gnittimda emit drah a dah I fi neve dna
.dnuora meht fo ynam nees t’ndah I
.daehA desolC daoR“ ,daer taht
?gnihtemos em llet ot gniyrt saw ykceB ekil
.tib elttil a tsuj xaler em edam hcihw
,elcihev s’tac eht fo edis eht otni deneerac dna
.niar gniruop eht htiw pu peek t’ndluoc llits hcihw ,srepiw gnipmuht eht ot kcab denrut dna
dliuG ’sretirW yrruF eht fo rednuof eht saw eH
.su dniheb deliart taht ssenkrad gnimool eht yb demusnoc eb ot ylno
.mra s’nosillA debbarg dna dnah gnilbmert ym htiw revo dehcaer I
redluohs ym debbarg yllanif nosillA litnu
snoitcerid lla ni lenparhs tew gniyarps
eht dna ,redduhs em edam tI
em gnitniop saw tI
,dleihs evitcetorp reh nepo nosillA dehctaw ylgnikatsniap I sa
.srehto eht morf tnereffid saw ehs
delaeuqs elcihev rehto eht no serit eht tub
.thginot neppah ot gniog saw gnihtemos wenk I dna
.evisneffo dnuos t’ndluow taht erecnis gnihtemoS
sdne yrots eht woh tuo dnif ot emit txen
.luos s’ykceB ym dewollaws dna efil ot gnurps dah niar eht erehw ecalp eht ot
,enigne s’rac eht derif
.naeco eht otni gnignulp erofeb htaerb tsal ym gnikat erew I fi sa
-I …ro lamina na ekiL
.ykceB fo em dednimer tac taht ,doG tub
.yltnereffid tib a
.em ot kcab noitnetta reh detfihs ehs erofeb llaw eht no kcolc eht ta pu kool ot tnemom a gnikat ,deksa ehs
pu depmarc teef defooh ym dna
.mlac sa ylraen t’nsaw I
ylgnikoj denoitseuq nosillA
”,taht tuoba yrros m’I“
elffins lufniap ,deggar a delahni I
.ecaf ym fo tnorf ni dnah reh devaw ehs sa
,detsuahxe dednuos srepiw ehT
elims a fo tnih tsetniaf eht ,deirt I drah woh rettam oN
,rednow tub pleh t’ndluoc I dna ,tuo ward ot deunitnoc noitanimaxe reh sa delgnit enips yM
.mih dnuora lla gnigar mrots eht htiw sdnema ekam ot yrt dna
.retsaf og ot su detnaw I
draobroolf eht tsniaga gnikcalc fooh ym saw ti
ehca deggaj a gnisuac
,esolc saw I wenk tsaeb ehT
.etal oot dnuora kcits t’nod tsuJ“  .delims ehS
.niar eht saw ereht neht dnA
.liar draug wol eht otni degnab dna
.ssenrettib ym evresed t’ndid ehs
.allerbmu reh fo ytefas eht rednu teg ot yrt neve t’ndid I
,thgil fo tsrub suotiuqibu a ekil dnim ym ni dehsalf thgin taht fo stneve ehT
.egnirc em edam llits noiton eht--tsirhC tub ,htiw nigeb ot rof dereenigne erew ew tahw s’taht dezilaer I  ”?syendik yM
sduolc eht morf nwod ruop ot deunitnoc niar eht sa tub
,tnedicca eht retfa tsaeb eht raen og reven dluow I flesym dlot I
,taorht ym ni pmul eht dewollaws I
.nwo reh no tuo ti erugif ot demees nosillA dna
.daor eht fo edis eht morf su ta gniralg saw egassem derrulb A  .ti was I nehT
.ytrof-owt nwod og su ekam t’nod …doG esaelP
.noitcelfer ym ees ot ylthgils os reve daeh ym detfil tub ,detatiseh I
.deddon I ,niagA  ”?erus uoY“
.rood eht denepo ydaerla dah I
.gge na tsegni ot gniyrt ekans a ekil
,sregnif defooh reh htiw em walc dna tuo hcaer ot gnitpmetta erew ykceB fi sa tlef tI
.lufraeF  .won deniarts saw eciov reH
?emit siht tnereffid os leef ti did yhw tuB
.riah esraoc dna niks hguor ym tsniaga gnitivni ylegnarts tey
thgil der sti hguorht deps elcihev evissam ehT
.dehtolc ylluf llits saw I erus ekam ot tsuj nwod gnicnalg pleh t’ndluoc I dna
,dias nosillA ”,dnuora yaw gnol eht ekat ot evah annog er’ew ekil skool tI“  ”.ruoteD esU
,moor eritne eht llif ot demees taht allinav fo tnih a dna
,edis sti otno rac eht deppilf mutnemom ehT
.elbmuts traeh ym edam tI
wenk I nehw s’tahT
.draobroolf eht revo lla gniripsrep dna tsalb lluf gninnur saw taht esoh rekaos a ekil tlef I dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,thgin eht hguorht dekaerts yeht sa
;seno doog eht fo eno saw ehS
,yawa dnim ym ekat ot gnihtemos ,no etartnecnoc ot gnihtemos dedeen I
.rac eht morf ksuh sselefil reh devomer dna
.niar fo stelpord eguh eht naht redrah neve rac s’nosillA fo wodniw eht detlep taht
,tug ym otni knas traeh yM
esuap gniusne ehT
,htiw revo siht teg ot emit saw tI
.ereht tuo og ot evah d’I
.tnemom a rof niar eht ffo dnim ym koot ti tsael ta tub
ladep sag eht no pets yllanif ot nosillA rof
,demaercs dna delwoh dniw ehT
?enahS ,uoy ot neppah gnihtemos did …iD“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.taebtraeh gnireviuq ym gnihctam dna
siht ekil ;won esle ydobemos evlovni ot gniog saw ti naem taht did tuB
,tuo gnimoc sedalb rozar ekil tlef sdrow ehT
,ylgnisirprus dna ,srae yppolf ym fo hctiwt elpmis a htiw ti did I  ”?tahW“
,daeh ym ni tsuj saw ti wenk I
,emas eht did dna allerbmu reh desolc ylkciuq nosillA
rethgit elttil a leehw gnireets eht pirg reh deciton I
”.oot eb d’I  .esnet os er’uoy rednow on s’tI
,ti timda ot detah I hcum woh rettam oN
,drow eht tuo tel ylteiuq I  .nwod edispu
.niks erihskroY etihw ,erup taht
”!thguohtretfa denmaddog fo tros emos ekil ecneitnes ruo detaert uoY“
,avliS coruD naeS yb
yaw egnarts a dah dlrow siht ni esle gnihtyreve woh ekil tsuj
.dnatsrednu t’ndluow ehs wenk I tub
,esnopser ym htiw desaelp t’nsaw ehs llet dluoc I
.denword ehS“  .tuo gniruop
,nosillA htiw rac eht ni tog evah t’ndluohs I
;maerd dab a eb ot dah tI
.retfa ytnewt ylraen s’tI“
.rood eht tuo dedaeh ew dna
;tnetsisrep saw ehS
retaw eht fo tuo elcihev reh dellup yeht sa
seye gniwolg htiw swodahs eugav naht erom gnihton ekil dekool
.deraef I tahw yltcaxe em gnillet
.nethgit ot detrats taorht ym sa ylyoc dias I
ot ekil t’nod uoY“
.em rof llac eciov eninimef
,tnecs tnasaelp a dah yllautca ydob reH
,egdirb eht gnissorc erew eW
nosillA draeh I nehw s’tahT
nosirp yretaw reh morf epacse ot gniyrt
.ti draeh I emit yreve saw I tnereffid woh tsuj em dednimer tI  .namuh yllufniap …os
.eman taht detah I ,doG  ”?enahS“
.gnirettahc erew hteet yM
draobllib elibom gnihsalf eht ees ot gnilggurts ,detniuqs I
.latem eht ssorca swalc rieht gnippat ylsuorogiv
,ssenkrad eht hguorht decreip sthgildaeh fo riap gnizalb a ,tfel ruo morF
taht lufknaht neeb ev’dluohs I sseug I tuB
,rood nepo eht morf em ta dekool ehS  ”.tiaw--nosillA“
.ti pots ot od dluoc su fo yna gnihton saw erehT
.ton ro ot detnaw I rehtehw ,retsnom eht tnorfnoc ot evah ot gniog saw I
.ti dnuora dnah ym denethgit I sa kaerc deniarts a tuo tel eldnah rood eht dna ,ydob ym pu derehtils egniwt suovren ehT
.ot demotsucca os nworg d’I nrecnoc namuh gnikool ekaf taht dewohs reven ecaf reh ,em ta dekool ehs nehW
.reh dezylarap yliratnemom
,sdrow eht dnif t’ndluoc I ,lausu sA
dluoc I ria tahw gnidraoh
.taem fo bals nmad a ekil
pu reh dewollaws taht tsaeb eht fo dnuos ehT
,yb gnillor tpek emit dna
.pots t’ndluow tsuj tI
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
em barg dna drawrof egnul thgim ti taht raef rof
deppop selkcunk yM
.noitcerid etisoppo eht morf su drawot gnideeps erew taht srac eht ta kcab gnikool pleh t’ndluoc I dna
.seirtnasaelp htiw doog reven saw I
.taht retfa emac ti ysae woh desirprus saw I
”.gnihtyna ro em retfa gnimoc s’ti ekil toN
.eno siht ekil tsuj thgin a no
raor gniohce na tuo tel
,emarf ynit reh revo decnalg I
.taht ekil gnihtemos revo teg t’nod uoy--enahS“
.niar eht fo deracs eb ot esucxe on llits s’ti--llew ,haeY“
”.emit gnol ,gnol a ni siht ekil niar ti nees t’nevah I“
ezilaer ot tnemom a em koot ti dna ,rac eht edisni gnilttar a draeh I
.dnopser t’ndid I
tnemdrabmob eht hguorht yaw ym thguof I
.tnurg detsugsid a tuo tel I sa
,snaej ym edisni hctiwt ot nageb liat ylruc ym sa
saw ydobemos ekil dednuos ti dna
,gnidnuos lufniap tsomla
edistuo esion eht gnillud
.reraelc mees segami eht edam ylno ti tub ,sdileye ym dniheb edih ot deirt I
.mitciv rehtona rof gnihcraes
reverof ekat ot demees ti esuaceb ,su dniheb saw eno on ,yllufknahT
”.ot tnaw uoy fI  .em llet nac uoy--oy …lleW“
rac eht edisni gniohce saw hcihw
.liar draug latem eht fo pot eht revo dellor elcihev eht sa
tnurg detarepsaxe ehT
,dne no doots kcen ym no sriah der ehT
.ytrof-owt etuor otno peerc dluoc rac eht os
,noisiv ym ni ecnuob lanac eht dehctaw I
.noitom ni tes neeb ydaerla dah stneve eht tub ”,oN“
”?ssap ot mrots eht rof gnitiaW“
.tuons ym ffo gnippird saw taht retaw eht fo emos ni dekcus I elihw
”?gniht lamina na ti sI“
,taes ym ni nezorf saw I
.noitcesretni eht hguorht rac rellams hcum s’enilef eht evord ti sa depmuj neve ylerab kcurt yvaeh ehT
enotsbmot latem nekorb s’ykceB revo dednuob I sa ydob ym no gnidnuop detrats ti esuaceb
”.ereh ti ekil uoy kniht thgim yehT
”niaR eht ni tsaeB ehT“
raef sih tnorfnoc ot decrof si enahS nehw
.rac eht retfa gnisahc nogard ylacs ,gnol a ekil
.kcab ti dloh t’ndluoc I  .esnopser larutan eht eb ot demees tsuj
,noitaerc rewen a erew yehT
detrats tsuj sdrow eht dna
”.yrros os m’I …I ,doG yM“
,rednet os tlef yehT
”,enif m’I--I ,oN“    .yawyna meht fo tsom ,lleW  .meht rehtob ot demees tahT
.laeuqs gnidnuos elbatrofmocnu
.sniarb ruo hguorht ecreip ot
?ta gnikool yllaer ehs si tahW“
,sruo fo tnorf ni gnidils tnew selcihev owt eht sa smaercs gnizinoga ekil dehcnurc dna deppop lateM
.selibomotua owt eht htiw sdraillib gniyalp erew doG fi sa
,ksa ot evah t’ndid I
.ereht tuo mih htiw toN
,denrecnoc dednuos ehS  .deddon I
,enilef orhtna gnuoy a ekil dekool revird eht tub
-edisni gniog yllautca saw I won tub
.peels peed a morf pu nekow tsuj dah I fi sa
,yawrood eht ni ereht gnidnats ydob enicrop reh was I nehw depsag ylraen I         .ykceB saw ti-
,sreh ot pu kcab delevart seye ym yllautnevE
.dnatsrednu ot demees nosillA
.rednaw seye reh tel ot ytinutroppo eht koot nosillA dna
werd taht pets hcae htiw gnisopmi erom dna erom gniworg
”,1-1-9 llaC“
;ffits erew sgel yM
”.gniht namuh a fo erom s’ti--yllautca …oN“
”.esnet yllaer ,yllaer
tuons ym fo tuo ylivaeh dehtaerb I sa roolf elit eht tsniaga sleeh reh fo skcilc prahs eht ot gninetsil
.rac eht gnivird saw ehs elihw denethgirf reh evah ot saw dedeen I gniht tsal eht dnA
…fi taht dias ecilop eht tuB
,em tnuah ot deganam llits taht esion ylno eht erew
”?niaga etal krow uoy gnikam nosnehpetS sI
.bos gnidnep eht elfits ot tpmetta na ni
htaerb a ni dekcus I
,ylsuovren derettum nosillA ”…enahS“
.ti fo erus edam I
elohw rac eht wollaws ot detpmetta eh sa rednu ti gnillup
.tuo dnif ot yaw eno ylno saw erehT
,larutannu os tlef tI
.thgir ym ot ecnalg tub pleh t’ndluoc I
.seye reh fo sedis eht morf em ta gnicnalg
.htuom ym ni deid tsuj sdrow eht tub ,dnopser ot tnaw em edam ti dna
,tluaf reh t’nsaw tI
,spets wef yreve tub
.reh rewsna ot detnaw llits I tub ,truh ot detrats gnihtyrevE
.oot eciov sih fo dnuos eht deirrac retaw eht esuaceb saw tI    .yhw wenk I dnA
.ti did lla yehT  .esoppus I
,peed ni dehtaerb I
.neppah did gnihtemoS  .haeY“
,em ot kcab gnihtemos derettum ehS  ”!woN
dna seye tfos esoht htiw em ta kcab gnizag
ti wenk tsaeb eht dna
.rac eht edisni flesreh delaes ehs sa
leef ti did yhw dnA
,wodniw tnorf tew eht hguorht dereep I
,ees ylerab dluoc I
,avliS coruD naeS yb
gnirevoh daeh reh
,elcihev reh fo ytefas eht deretne dna
taes ym ni derevihs I
.lanac eht otni tnew ti dna elcihev reh fo lortnoc tsol ehS
.did ew tub ,etatiseh t’ndid su morf ssorca enilef ehT
,ti leef dluoc I  .thgir t’nsaw gnihtemos wenk I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.noitcesretni eht ssorca enal etisoppo eht ni gnitiaw saw taht rac eht ta gnirats
-eromyna nosillA t’nsaw ti ylnO
tsaeb eht erofeb yliratnemom gnihsalf
.yawyna thginot toN  .gniniar pots ot gniog t’nsaw ti yhw s’tahT
.ssecorp eht gnirud erehwemos yalp otni emoc ot scihte wolla ot hguone dnik erew
”.ti revo teg ot nrael ot deen I …I sseug I
.kcab eht ni allerbmu reh dessot ehs sa yas ot detrats nosillA ”…taht tsuj s’ti
”.nosillA ,worromot uoy ees ll’I“
.spordraet gnillor ekil wodniw eht fo edis rehto eht nwod elkcirt retaw fo smaerts ynit eht gnihctaw
,raelc yltcefrep snoitnetni sih edam ydaerla dah tsaeb ehT
,efas saw ti erehw edisni kcab emoc ot reh detnaw I
,yrroS“  .taes reh otni delttes ehs sa
?em fo tnorf ni gnidnats saw ohw elamef ednolb ,ynit
.elcihev reh fo foor eht ta decnalg I sa raor tsaeb eht draeh I nrows evah dluoc I
.reh did ti ekil tsuj
.gniraew saw ehs tius eulb yvan
,ecnatsid eht ni su ta deralg thgil der elgnis a tub
,ti dniheb daor eht htiw lellarap gninnur retaw eht ees dluoc I
.smlap ym otni kcab sregnif defooh ym gniggid
,yvaeh a htiw ni evag yllautneve I tub
.sreh fo stigid namuh niht esoht htiw dnah nevolc ym debbarg ehs sa
.deneppah taht nehw ti detah I
,rits em edam tahT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,niar yvaeh eht ni llet ot tluciffid saw tI
,tnemom a rof detatiseh ehS
”?em gnillet ton er’uoy gnihtemoS
,drawrof denael ehs sa retteb hcum gniraf eb ot mees t’ndid nosillA dna
,ylpeed delahni I dna
,potfoor eht no gnicnad swalc sih raeh dluoc I
,thginot yrgnuh saw eH
.eciov fo enot evitisop reh htiw taebpu dnuos ot gnitpmetta
”,dnim t’nod uoy erus uoy
,yhw erus ton llits m’I dna ,sruoh rof tuo ward ot demees
smaeb gniralg sti gnihctaw dna
,dekciw rehtona tuo tel niar eht draeh I nehT
,ydob enicrop ym detcepsni ylluferac ehS
tsuj yllautneve dluow tsaeb eht dna daeh ym ni lla saw siht derugif I
ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,hguoht nosillA ton tuB
.hsalps a htiw decnelis erew sevooh ym fo pans eht
secips tniaf fo dnelb psirc a ekil
.leehw gnireets eht revo tsuj
.deddon dna seye ym desolc I
.erots yrecorg a fo sevlehs eht gnihcraes saw ehs ekil nwod dna pu ti gnikool
,ciots deniamer I tub ”,evah I“
,tnagele eht otni deraeppasid ti llit niks naisacuaC thgil taht dna riah ednolb fo sdnarts gnol esoht gnicart
nosillA sa delaeuqs sekarb tew ehT
.rac eht fo tuo gnippets erofeb nosillA ot dias I
kcurt gnimocno eht ta gnikool
;tresed a sa yrd sa tlef ylneddus htuom ym ,elcihev eht fo edistuo eht gnitlep retaw eht lla htiw nevE
,ti esol ot gnitrats saw I ekil tlef I
,noziroh eht dellif thgil fo tsrub dekciw a nehT
,kaeps ot tnaw t’ndid I hguoht neve dna
.rac eht fo edis ym no ladep ekarb elbisivni na rof hcaer ot gniyrt saw I ekil ,draobroolf eht otni meht desserp I sa
,eid ot gniog saw enilef tahT
”.yako eb ll’I  .oN“
.nosillA ta kool ot detfihs I sa nosinu ni gnikrow detrats yllanif ydob ym dna
”?uoy od …hcum klat
.rehtona ro yaw eno ni ykceB gnilbmeser fo
.taht em llet ot gniyrt saw su dnuora gnihtyreve ekil demees ti dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.noitcesretni depahs-T eht ta elcihev eht deppots
,won psarg sih ni saw ehS
.daeha pu tsuj daor eht gnola snur taht eno ehT
.kcart no kcab daeh ym teg dluow ti taht gnipoh
.yks eht detsalb taht rednuht fo kcarc rehtona htiw em ot dellac eh dna
evaeh ot nageb sgnul yM
.edih t’ndluoc I egniwt suovren a em evag tI
.ecnart dexif ym morf em derraj dna
.tnurg gnihca eht kcab dloh t’ndluoc I
…won si ti ekil tsuj gniniar saw ti dnA  .daor siht no-
ti did eh dna ;luos reh deruoved dna
,dnoces a ylno rof su deyaled tI
od dluoc ehs ylno ekil
.sesoprup citemsoc rof yltsom dna
.gnidliub eht fo ecnartne eht ta ecalp reh ekat ylelos ot nosillA gnivael
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”?’nihtemos siht
esuaceb ,ecamirg eht gnidih ta saw I lufsseccus woh erus t’nsaw I
.pleh rof seirc delffum reh htiw
”niaR eht ni tsaeB ehT“ fo
,tnemevap eht tsniaga dekcarc teef defooh yM
;retaw eht ta kool ot raeb neve t’ndluoc I
gnilggig pots ot flesreh decrof ehs esuaceb
.eramthgin a t’nsaw ti wenk I
.htuom s’retsnom eht fo teef net nihtiw nar dna
.deeps ot pu kcab dnim ym gnirb ot gnitpmetta ,ylthgils daeh ym koohs I dna
ecno deppilf elcihev s’tac eht sa dehctaw I nehT
,noitcesretni eht fo elddim eht morf em ta derats worra wolley ,egral ehT
.degrembus yletelpmoc tsomla saw rac eht ,neht yB
.rac reh ot revo hsur ot gniraperp
,htiw derewsna ylraen I dna
.niap eht edih ot tpmetta deliaf a ni sredluohs ym gnillor
.mrots eht otni repeed
.degnahc serit eht fo hctip eht ,elim a naht ssel retfA
rac eht ssorca dehcaer ehS
”?edir a tnaw uoY“
,thguoht eht ta degnirc I
.tahw wonk t’nod I-
;tnedicca reh ot kcab
.em fo edisni kcab lruc dna pu dlof ot tuoba erew sevooh ym ekil leef em edam ti dna
.lanac eht sdrawot gnidaeh
.hcum taht reh evig ll’I
,gnilaeppa yllacitehtsea deredisnoc yltcaxe t’nerew eniwS
”?yako uoy erA“  .namuh a rof-
.taes pmad ylthgils won eht tsniaga ydob ym dexaler I sa drow rehtona yas t’ndid I
,gniod saw I tahw esnes dluoc niar eht kniht I
,stsif ym denethgit I sa
.elbmurg gnilkcac ,wol a htiw em deteerg eh sa
.siht od em ekam t’noD
epat noituac fo eceip ysmilf a ekil elkcub ot edacirrab eht gnisuac
enal etisoppo eht ni su yb delias taht selcihev ehT
.esnopser etairporppa na rehtegot llup ot gniyrt saw ehs llet dluoc I  ”.em srehtob tI
.srae gnipoord ym ot yaw sti dekans taht
.ykceB saw eman reH“
niaga ereht gnidnats flesym was I
.murd ognob cinomed a no gniliaw dlihc a ekil rac eht fo foor eht tsniaga gnilttar detrats niar fo doolf tpurba na sa
gnihtyreve derrulb taht retaw fo reyal eht hguorht ees ot gniyrt ,semit lareves seye ym deknilb I
,rac eht tlep ot deunitnoc retaw ehT
.ti denepo dna rood eht ot revo deklaw ehs ,taht htiW
,tser ot emac yllanif kcurt ehT
tnemevap tew eht ssorca deunitnoc ti sa
.etal oot ydaerla saw ti tub ,maercs ot htuom reh denepo ehs ekil dekool tI
.tuo yaw eht no eugnot ym ssorca gnikar erew sdrow eht fi sa demees ti dna
.niaga gnihgual detrats ehS
.ngis pots eht ot emac ew sa ffo pans ot gniog saw ti thguoht I
.emit hguone flesreh evig t’ndid ehS
,liar draug dellatsni ylwen eht no srotcelfer eht thguac sthgildaeh ruO
,ssendas eht kcab knilb ot dah I
ni demihc nosillA
.emit gnol a ni delims t’ndah I  .driew tlef tI
;ekohc ot em gnisuac ylraen
nosillA ta kool ot nageb I sa
-ereh deneppah yllautca tI“  .ot dedeen I
.tnurg ot ton flesym ecrof ot dah I
,krad eht drawot sucof ym gnitfihs dna seye ym gniworran yb lla ti erongi ot deirt I
.saw enim ekil tsuj ,ydob reh ffo gnitaidar raef eht llems dluoc I
,noitcesretni eht fo elddim eht ni saw ehS
.edisbus reven dluow sekahs ym thguoht I ,tnemom a roF
.llah eht fo dne rehto eht morf neve
”?em raeh uoy nac ,enahS ot htraE  ?enahS“
dna …won oga sraey owt ylraen deneppah tahT  .nosillA ,enif s’tI“  .dekrow reven tI
.enots evarg tfihsekam a ekil tuo dnats ti gnikam
,sdlroW tnereffiD
.rac neknus eht drawot gninnur detrats I sa
.efil ot gnimoc detrats eh sa
.neerg denrut thgil eht nehw s’tahT
.dedeen ew lla saw taht tub
,evisneherppa llits saw enot reH
,sraet rof deen eht dnatsrednu t’ndid stcnitsni ruO
”.enoyna dlot reven ev’I gnihtemoS
.krow t’ndid ti tub ,reh egaruocsid dluow ti thguoht I  ”.oN“
.srotpac sih yb netaeb gnieb renosirp a ekil emarf ykcots ym no gnidnuop
.did ykceB ym ekil tsuj
,teiuq a ekil tuo emac ti tub ,dehgual ylraen I
,ssalg eht tsniaga dnah nevolc ykahs ym decalp I  2 fo 1 traP
,retaw eht fo rettalc gniremmah eht ta dekcilf srae yM
.gninrom eht ni em ot txen pu ekow ehs nehw delkraps seye reh yaw eht neve ro ,hgual reh ,elims reH
dlofnu eganrac eht gnihctaw
,taes eht ni pu flesym denethgiarts I
,riaf ytnuoc eht ta noitcua eht gnirud tlef srotsecna ym yaw eht neeb evah tsum sihT
kniw a htiw deksa nosillA ”?ydaer uoY“
.rac eht morf yawa teef ytnewt naht ssel on saw hcihw
.siht ekil syad no reh ekil kool ot demees enoyreve ,niaga nehT
”…ev’thgim ehs kniht yeht
.reh teem ot denrut dna
.pal ym otni gnippord seye ym ,desuap I
tuons ym morf yawa retaw eht depiw dna eson ym dehctiwt I
t’niA“         .sthgildaeh gnimocno eht fo neehs gnidnilb eht diova em pleh saw did ti lla teY  .daor gnitivninu
.edistuo ynohpocac eht morf ecaep s’tnemom a flesym evig ot gniyrt ,taes eht ni kcab denael dna
.dnoces yna ta pu ekaw ot detcepxe I
,sdaor dna steerts fo naeco krad ,tsav taht ni ,erehwemoS
.4 emuloV raoR dna ygolohtnA sdrawA ltoyoC eht ni
,elcihev eht tsniaga dehsalps dna deppals sgnaf tew siH
”…wonk uoy …tsuj s’tI“
.orhtna eninac ro tac gnikool suoromalg erom a morf yendik a ro traeh a yub ot denilcni erom hcum demees snamuh dna
”niaR eht ni tsaeB ehT“   :yojne esaelP
.erom ecno dne no doots yeht sa denrub ydob ym revo lla sriah der krad
dnah ykahs ym htiw sraet yarts eht yawa gnipiw
strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.htuom ym fo segde eht ecarg ot deganam
,avliS coruD naeS yb
?gnorw gnihtemos si …enahS“
,tnemknabme eht nwod
,saw yas ot detnaw yllaer I tahw
.niar taht ,doG hO
,noitingi eht otni yek eht tup ehS
,noitcefni na ekil stcnitsni lamina desufnoc eht ffo thgif ot deirt yllarutan niarb eht ,yrc ot detrats sorhtna nehw dna
.lla s’taht ,niar eht ekil t’nod tsuj I“
…yeht tub deneppah tahw erus yltcaxe ton er’yehT
!ti oD“  ”.tiaw--enahS“
,resolc gnitteg namuh etitep eht llems dluoc eh em llet ot gniyrt erew tsaeb eht fi sa saw tI
.sreh fo seye eulb elttil tneconni yltcefrep esoht dna ,elims gniwolg taht htiw em ta gnizag saw ehS
.retaw eht ot resolc em
-ytterp saw erus nosillA