)oga gnol yrev ton ,swonk tesnus ehT( nrut ot esle erehwon dah ecno I nehw tahT
tsuj nehw semit ehT ni ecnesba ruoy leef I' dna 'uoy ssim I'
emoc srehto nehw
.niaga dexif ma I nehw
.egap yrruFoS sih no
,evol ym ,flesruoy ksa uoy esle revetahW ).tesnus eht
.tser tesnus eht ni dna
,seohs tuo-nrow ynam oot ,ralloc god A
ria tresed sseldniw eht ,wonk I ,wenk uoY
.teop eht yb daeR
,tsniaga denraw snortam deppil-sserp worran tahT
.erofeb ega yna naht raf resiw er'yehT ,em ot erew uoy ylimaf dna emoh dnA efil fo dnik eht ,eseht morf ,sseug nac yeht fI
),syad ym no tesnus tey ton sit yarp I(
”flesyM ksA I sgnihT ehT“ saw sihT
.teop eht yb daer ,floWcaM boR yb
?edis dna sdnah ym nopu borht taht esoht roF
,syad ym fo tesnus eht raen erehwon llitS ,tem evah I ti si woh ,flesym ksa I
.edis ruoy yb em evresed uoy fi ton ksA
.edis ruoy yb em tnaw uoy taht ylno tuB
,sevren ruoy ssorcA dehcte ecnis gnol noituac dna ytleurc tahT sracs eht lla sregnif gniveilebsid htiW decart I fI
,tsew rettu fO setag eht ssap uoy erofeb eseht hguorht ssap llahS
?uoy htiw saw I erehw srebmahc eht dnif oT ,efil fo ezam eht ni ,sega erutuf fO seye eht dael dluoc liart bmurcdaerb fo dnik tahW
,gnirac os yb ,tI ,eid ro evil dluohs I taht erac ot eno oN
,etubirtnoc ot esle enoyna stcepxe eh fi ,lla retfa ohw ,floWcaM boR yb
syad ruo fo tesnus eht dessap sah retfA
).os ti lliw tesnus yaM( .dnoyeb ,eya dnA
,gnivresednu lla ,evah I swonk tesnus dnA(
smeop dna seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.ekil sleef efil tahw si siht—
dellirht si llits teY
'.gniveirg morf tser em gnirb dluoW ybraen esolc uoy evah ot
edis ruoy yb noitseuq tuohtiw dna ecno tA eb em tel ,gniveirg morf tser uoy gnirb dluoW raen em evah ot tsuj taht
ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot
?rehtohcae rof ,ereh tliub ecnO I dna uoy tahw dnatsrednu meht ekam dluoC
,evresed I fi ,flesym ksa ton od I
,gnittes eb ot yad eno devorP nus elbarelotni taht nehw
”,flesyM ksA I sgnihT ehT“ si meop s’yadoT
.llems aes tlas tnatsid eht ro ,retniw nI  thgileldnac ro
),tey sedaced rof tsal tesnus eht yarp I ,syad ym fo tesnus eht eb siht fi dnA(
?I did sa ylpeed sa riapsed uoy diD
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.niar desselb tfos evah I
.yrteop fo sparcs emos ,snac ados emoS
.ton od I taht eb yam tI .uoy evah oT
,flesym ksa netfo I
.seert fo dnuos eht evah I .sthgin retniw nO emalf eht evah I
.dnefed lliw reve
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf
.syad ym fo tesnus eht litnu won morF
gnihtyna ton ,etiteppa ton ,tsul toN
,uoy pleh lliw revE ydoboN—
,flesym ksa I ,neht tuB
,syad ym fo tesnus eht morf raf os llitS ,emoc evah I ti si woh ,flesym ksa I
kram d'xif reve na si taht dnik ehT
hctam a meht dnif I dluow
),efil ym ot tesnus a hcus htiw tnetnoC eb dluow I ,tesnus eht erew siht fi dnA(
).tnuoc ton seod taht tub ,enildoolb sih fo eM tpecca ot yad eno ,tesnus eht yarp I(
).gniveirg morf tser deen I deedni hcum woH swonk tesnuS(
,yrotsih tahw ,erol fo yretsam tahW
,”flesyM ksA I sgnihT ehT“   yojne esaelP
.llew sa trap sih od ot gnilliw eb ot thguo
floWcaM boR yb meop a
,niar eltneg ot 'evresed' on s'erehT
.stnemunom on ,ygolaeneg oN ,moolrieh on
,flesruoy deksa uoy hcum woh ,flesym ksa I
.taht fi ,muinnellim a ni ecno tuB despmilg ylno gnihtemos si eveileb uoy evaH dluow steop
"?ria eht evresed uoy oD"
,ygoloehcra tahw ,enog era ew dnA
).tesnus sa gniht hcus saw erehT wenk I erofeb gnol tesnus rof deyarp I( ?em rof sa
—yaw eht yb evael I dna uoy sa hcus oD secart tahW
gnuoY saW dlroW eht nehW ni mih dnif nac uoY
em dednimeR  ,yldetcepxenu
,dexif naht ssel ma I nehw dnim ton seod teY
.ylimaf a siht dnA .emoh a si sihT
,dniw eht tsniaga seert fO dnuos ro
efil ym fo tesnus eht raen woh swonk ohW
yas uoy raeh ot elbissop si ti erehW efil fo ezam eht ni rebmahc emos otnU
.aes fo llems eht evah I .ria eht evah I
,uoy roF  ytilibissopmi hcum sa ti saW
),esrev a ni ti edih tsum ,swonk tesnus ,tuB( ,nialp uoy ksa ot traeh eht ton evah I roF
nossel eno tub sehcaet dnA
ksa ot kniht dluow etircopyh tnadep tahW
).edis ym yb seunitnoc htap ruoy dnif I  ssap tesnus taht ot I nehw taht yarp I(
taht evol fo deerb erar taht htiW
,stes reven dna ,ytleurc si nus erehW
llew sa uoY .elpoep rehto rof devreseR  ylevisulcxe ton era sgniht eseht lla dnA
yas llahs uoy nehW .uoy rof evil I
,enildoolb on ,eman ylimaf oN
),eb llahs yeht ohw swonk tesnus neve toN(
?erudne uoy did gnol woh ,drol ho ,gnol woH
.meht rof evil ton od I ?erac I od tahw