.emoh s’noediG ni deraeppa latrop rehtona dna
”.snaebxoF noediG .rM ,sruoy ekil tsuj ,heH“
.rood nepo eht ot nar eh ,sraet hguorht gnitniuqS
.pukaerb ym retfa tops ralimis a ni saw I kniht I
”.gnikrow t’nsi dnah thgir ym ,yeh -naht retteb
”?uoy ot yllis dna erutammi sraeppa tsuj modnaF eht ni gnineppah s’tahw fo tol a ,sraey tnecer ni ,sseug em teL“
.noitide ylrae detimil yrev eht rof muimerp a diap I
.shtnom eerht ni hcnual lliw taht eno ehT
”?’sdik‘ gniyas tsuj fo daetsni ’seippup‘ dna ’redael kcap‘ ekiL“
”.-ot sCPN ekil erom era yeht ,enif s’tI“
noitasnes emoclew a erew selit roolf looc s’moorhtab ehT
.erom erolpxe ot detnaw eH
.sratava tnereffid no deirt dna
”.yadseuT txen draob dna OEC eht htiw gniteem
,dlrow lautriv eht ni tneps sruoh eseht lla retfA
.thguoht eh ,erutaef tnellecxe nA
.pu kcab natrapS denrut dna
.dnesdog a dnekeew eht dna yadkrow eht fo dne eht
.dniheb siht lla evael dluohs eh dna erutammi saw gniht elohw eht wenk rehto eht
.ti htrow s’tI“ .dias noediG
.llah eht fo dne raf eht ta rood detniap etihw
.nuf tub gnihtyna ekil dednuos - dlrow lautriv a ni yllaicepse ebyam
.siht gnitseggus rof sknaht ,yeh dnA
,syadhtrib ,samtsirhC
.dekrow ti woh dnatsrednu ot sdnuor wef a mih koot tI
.dlihc renni eht ot gninetsil tuoba mih dlot natrapS tahw derebmemer noediG
.gnirob rehtar lla era yeht tub
.skrow sih ni gnignoleb dna evol
,dneirf taerg a saw natrapS
.sparts eht gnitsujda no tpek
”?thgir ,amard dna kaerbtraeh nwo ruo hguorht tnew tsrif ew nehw su ot srettam ronim ton erew sgniht eseht …won taht gniyaS
.tiderc hcum oot meht evig ton dluow I tub
.seye sih ni sraet
,lleW“ .ti devas eH
.elbadnatsrednu gnieb llits elihw hguone tsuj dedaf dah seciov ehT
.tsrow eht era sexof ,yltsenoH“
”?uoy ot gniklat eulB sI“
.hguone riaf tub ,elpoep ynam oot ekil sdnuoS“
.serutseg regnif s’tI“
.regnuoy gnitteg dna gnignahc saw ti
.meht rof tseb eht s’tahw od dna ti tuoba kniht neve t’nod uoY
.ynootrac oot saw taht xof a htiw pu dedne noediG elihw ,htiw deifsitas ssel ro erom saw eh
emoh sih ta kcaB
.enips sih pu tperc raeF
ebyaM‘ .selpmet sih degassam eH .azalP negotorP
.laer rof uoy htiw elbat a ta gnittis m’I ekil leef tsomla I“
.emos tsael ta troppus sratava tsom draeh I
.latsedep ybraen a ot revo natrapS dewollof noediG .dias natrapS
sihT“ ”?raf os siht fo kniht uoy od tahw …oS“
”?yrutnec ts12 eht denioj yllanif uoy oS
”.ytinummoc siht morf yawa gnitfird er’uoy leef uoy dna evitca ssel dna ssel emoceb uoy modnaF eht nO
dellac ecalp a saw daol ot dlrow tsrif ehT
,reraen emac ecafrus ehT
.thguoht eht ta tliub elims wols A
suoirotciv saw thgin erofeb dessap ruoh rehtonA
…haeY“ ”?tnatropmi ti sI“
,spuorg ni tuoba derettacs sregnarts htiw degreme dlrow wen a noos dna
.delkcuhc natrapS
”?dlihc renni ruoy kcab gnirb sdik gnivah did woH“
tsuj s’tel erutuf ni dna ,oot ,eman ym egnahc ll’I .thgir
,dnim sih ta deppin aiglatson
- dlrow lautriv a ni neve ,elbaicos gnieb fo thguoht ehT .deksa noediG
.kcul elttil htiw stnemevom regnif sih cimim ot deirt eH
’.dneirf dlo ,paeh parcs eht rof ydaer htob er’ew sseug
…gnimrahc woh ,lleW“
rotavele eht dedoolf elpoep ,denepo srood eht nehW
.ereht ni saw ydoboN
.taht tuoba yrros ,haeY“
.rorrim eht fo edis rehto eht no
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadot dna
.tenretni eht no eb ot emit hguone tsuj dna krow neewteb sgniws taht muludnep eht naht efil ot erom saw ereht fi derednow eH
”.kniht I ,oot si enim ,lleW“
.setunim fo rettam a saw ni gniggol dna tnuocca na gniretsigeR
.latrop a pord em teL“
romra na ekil negotorp eht
.niaga revo dna revo selfirt emas eht htiw laed ot tnaw t’nod uoy dna og lliw ti erehw wonk uoy ,amard eht ees uoY .seod tI“
thgil derettacs eht morf yawa knas eh
.sedis owt no slatsedep wef a htiw dlrow llams a saw tI .thguoht eH
.dezzub ksed sih no enohptrams ehT .thguoht eH
,wonk uoY .ereht uoy teem ot ecin eb ll’tI .ti yrt s’teL“
.neht niaga gnineve worromot mih htiw teem ll’I .dnatsrednu lliw eh erus ma I ,thgirlA ?won thgir ,hO“
.rood desolc eht dniheb esion a saw erehT
?pu s’tahw ,redael kcap yeH“
.syad loohcs tsrif
’.oot ,ereht sratava fo sepyt rehto era ereht
.noitsuahxe s’yad eht fo emos dna emirg eht yawa dehsaw ecaf eht ot retaw dloc fo hsalps A
.sgel yrruf kciht dna ,srae yffulf
.seohs ssenisub ni yad a retfa
.ralucatceps gnihton
.ytingid ruoy peek t’nac uoy
,elgnis a tub nepo erew smoor eht llA
.eno yb eno sreyalp rehto eht gnillik ro
.tesdaeh wen ym tuo yrt ot gnineve eht ekat ot em dlot eulB ,netsiL .deb ni era seippup ehT“
”?esaelp ,em rof 41 rebmun sserp enoemos nac ,yeH“
.pu nepo mih pleh ot detnaw dneirf sih ebyaM
.esor eh ,rehtruf gniknis fo daetsni dna
.deraeppasid evah sraey evif ,eerht ot tnuoc nac uoy erofeb dna boj emit-lluf a otni teg uoy ,wonk uoY
gnidliub tnemtrapa eht fo yawllah ecnartne elbram eht ni deohce spetS
,modnaF eht ot ,ebyaM .redlO
.rellortnoc eht denepo dna srevirdwercs fo tes sih tuo koot eH .gnihtoN
,semag draob dnuof eh erehw sdlrow emag rehto derolpxe eH
”rorriM eht fo ediS rehtO ehT“
”.flesruoy gnieb tsuj dna og gnittel fo rettam a si tI
,erehwyreve gniylf sretnilps ,derettahs tI
.tobor rehtona was dna dnuora denrut noediG
tsap sih derednop eh ,dellevart eh sA
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.egasuas fo tib ,repapswen htiw denil part a nwod tup - gniht tseB“
”.diarfa eb ot tnaw t’nod I“
… ruo rof suomaf er’eW
,morf kcip ot sratava dradnats emos era rorrim eht ta revO“
.rorrim eht fo edis rehto eht morf negotorp eht saw
.peeb railimaf a htiw efil ot emac tI
,yawllah gninrub eht fo dne eht ta rood eht drawot nwod mih gnillup ytivarg tlef eH
”.krow edistuo ti gniylppa tuoba thguoht reven I taht suoiruC
.ffo denrut rellortnoc thgir ym ,oN“ ”?ko gnihtyrevE“
dna reh fo ecin s’tahT“
taht eno ,flow a dnuof natrapS
,ria eht dellif tnimreppep fo llems eht nehW
,emit gnitsaw ton er’uoY“
.yadot rof hcraes ratava sih dne tsael ta dluow tI
.regnessem no natrapS dellac dna yawa thgir tesdaeh sih no tup eH .delims noediG
,detuohs puorg raen a ni ydobemoS
?tog I elosnoc muimerp wen taht rebmemeR
;swollag eht morf nwod nekat gnieb ekil tlef
,seilfrettub ekil erew sthguoht sih
’!tesdaeh RV ym tog I
.doog ma I ,on ,oN“ .dias natrapS
.kniht uoy tahw s’tahT !aH“
,dekcolnu saw rood eht sa noos sA
.snoisserpxe laicaf latigid hguorht snoitome cisab dewohs taht rosiv a saw ecaf ehT
.yllis thgirtuo gnieb tsuj ro ,ssenisub nwo rieht gnidnim ,gniklat
.nekorbnu dna elohw llits saw efil sih nehw semit dlo rof gninraey dna gnirebmemer a
sessalg ym teg lliw I ,yakO“ ”.esaelp ,dad seY“ ”?ti rof kool uoy pleh ot em tnaw uoy oD
.’gnaffloW natrapS‘
.egairram ni yllaicepse ,seitivitca elgnis rof moor ekam ot deen uoY“
.dehgis noediG ”…derongi eb ot-“
”.owt uoy neewteb tuo gnikrow s’ti ees ot dalg ma I .taht teg I ,haeY“
.deirram era uoY .wonk t’nod I“ ”.rof
.rood eht dnoyeb morf gnihtemos draeh eh niagA
.ti eb os ,llabfoog a eb ot evah uoy snaem taht fI
.moor txen eht morf gnimoc taeh eht tlef dna
,sratava cilbup gnireffo ot detacided sdlrow ynam erew erehT
,ti dehcuot natrapS
;noitcelfer sih was eh dna ,dellits retaw
.rehto hcae fo kcis teg selpuoc esiwrehtO
.moor raen eht otni tnew dad siH
.dlo ton er’uoy ,traeh ta gnuoy er’uoy sa gnol sA“
no dloh ot gnihtyna rof depsarg eh sa
,fpmH“ ”?yaw eht yb ,krow s’woH“
;yawa gnitfird saw modnaf ehT
.puorg ega eno fo kramedart evisulcxe na ton si ssenhsiloof ,llew ,dnA
yeH‘ :natrapS morf egassem a saw tI
,meht htiw yalp uoy nehW
”?tey elpoep ynam oot toN“
.nwo sih no efac eht ta gniyats ekil leef ton did noediG
.tsud eht hguorht roolf nedoow derehtaew eht ssorca stnirptoof gnidaf fo kcart a dewollof eH
.tesdaeh RV sih fo tuo tog dna
dnuof noediG taht si ti tahw tuo dnif ot
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.uoy ees yldrah nac I
”.gnihtemos tsol I kniht I ,daD“
”?nuf eb ot desoppus s’taht ,mU“
.mih ta delims dna redluohs sih no dnah a tup dad siH
”.yllufepoh ,tib a ni uoy eeS .doog sdnuoS“
gnikool saw I
ebyaM‘ .edutitla gniniag yldipar
”.eciwt ekatsim taht ekam t’now I
”.niaga em nioj nac uoy erehw tsil sdneirf a evah uoy unem ruoy nI
.troffe taerg htiw moor eht fo ecnartne eht ot revo deklaw eh
.ereht ni saw ydobemoS
.gniniart pihsredael morf nossel taht rebmemer I
,hguorht deppets eh sA
”!ti pihs ot hguone gnol meht koot tI .tluaf ym toN“
- xoF eht noediG ,dnim sih nI
:txen eht dellif senecs reippaH
tsud eht hguorht edils ot gnitrats ydob sih
”.tiaw nac I ,rorrim eht ni fles namkcits ruoy ta gnikool emit erom dneps ot tnaw uoy fi ,hguone riaF“ ”?uoy era
”?eno taht deirt uoy evah ,rebaS taeB otni tog I
”?he ,efil laer ni ysae taht saw ti ylno fI“ .”retteB“
.ecnatpecca ,ylnedduS
.kool ruos a mih evag ratava s’natrapS
,eurT“ ”.ecitcarp emos deen lliw tahT“
.kcab eht ni eciov tniaf a dna esuap a saw erehT ”.lamron klat
.evoba gniliar a morf mih dellac natrapS
”?ecnaraeppa ruo tuoba od ew llahs tahw ,yakO
pirg sti gnisae dna eit eht gninesool ,yadoT
emarf eht revo regnif sih nar eH
.seirruF rof dlrow buh a em dednemmocer dneirf A“
”.yaw taht kniht smees ti sa elpoep ynam sa ton raf yB
.rotavele eht llac ot nottub eht desserp noediG ,emoh gnimoC
.yawa dekool eh dna
”.dlihc renni ruoy ot netsil uoy nehw dnif thgim uoy tahw swonk ohW
”…citnehtua fo gnikaepS“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT    .eerf saw eh dna
rosiv eht derewol
,nekorb dekool gnihtoN
”!ffo snrut dna toh snur gniht ydoolb tahT
’draoB dna OEC htiw gniteeM‘
,denethgit taorht s’noediG
”?ecaf ruos taht ekam uoy did woh ,tuB“
”rorriM eht fo ediS rehtO ehT“   yojne esaelP
.em llac ,eraps ot emit tog uoy fI
.yawllah dlo na fo sllaw eht no sotohp dedaf was noediG
.dnah thgir sih devaw noediG .deksa natrapS
”?daeha pu elbuorT“ .dias noediG
~ .maerd diviv a otni mih deggard dna
ffo deggol noediG
.tuo yaw sih decrof eh dna
egakcerw eht dleh tI
,hguorht em wolloF
.daeh sih koohs noediG
.ti dekil fo dnik eh taht flesmih ot timda ot dah eh tub
.ediseb dnuorg eht no ydob derevoc a htiw
!dessip os ma I ,doG“
”.yllautca ,enummi eb ot neppah I os ,elttil saw I nehw taht dah I ,sbmurc ,hO“
.railimaf gnihtemos tlef eH
,pu-pop a saw erehT
moc.yrrufos.ardik ta seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”.elpoep ot klat dna teem ,sdlrow dnuora klaw ,ratava na kcip nac uoY
,repsihw a draeh eh dnim sih nI
.dnatsrednu ton tub ,raeh dluoc eh taht sdrow
er’uoY“ ”.drah oot gniyrt ekil sleef ti ...haeY“
.niaga uoy teem ot worromot owt ro ruoh na rof enilno emoc ll’I ,esimorpmoc a sA
emit txen ni enuT
,yllis saw sihT .demlap-ecaf eH
,tsil hctaw sih ni seirtne wen wef a erew erehT
.mih ta kcab gnikool negotorp eht
”.egassem a uoy dnes lliw I neht ,ti ekam t’nac I fI .od lliw ,sknahT“
.os detseggus stsop emoS
.seiromem fo llah eht nwod llef eh ,erif
,ylimaf htiw semit lufyoJ
mih emacrevo mlac taerg A
”.hcum ytterp ,haey tub ,taht ekil ti esarhp ot tnaw t’ndiD“
.efil sih rof eurt saw emas eht won yb fi derednow eh dna
,ecalp gnimoclew a neeb dah modnaF ehT
.rorrim tseraen eht ot tnew dna demrofsnart noediG ,eno gnikcilC
”.ereh duol s’tI“ ”?gnorw gnihtemoS“
”…sisoripsotpel ,sisairacoxot daerps ,erehwyreve parC
.thgir tsuj tlef enon dna
.dnim sih ni dnuora decnuob rorrim eht ni was eh tahw fo ohce ehT
.emag redrum a saw taht dlrow a otni deppets eH
”?ereht teg ew od woH
.tsap eht ni tniop ralimis a ta erew lla ew
?ti wonk uoy ebyaM
,nruter ton did rehtaf sih nehw dna ,detiaw noediG
.dnim ni tnereffid gnihtemos dah I ,yadot roF
.sbat ni nepo ydaerla segapbew evif lausu eht
.rac CR ’sdik ym xif em gnipleh rof uoy knaht ot em deksa eulB ,yaw eht yB …os yas uoy fi
.elbisiv saw - tobor cireneg a - ratava na rorrim eht nI
.eil a ekil leef ot detrats taht tub
.ytpme dna ngierof tlef tnemtrapa sih
.deyaled noitucexe na
.democlew noitcartsid eht dna
,kcab og ot detnaw mih fo trap A
.gnisufnoc saw ti tub ,ratava wen siht fo dnof gniworg saw eh tlef eh dna
”.ton erew ylniatrec yeht ,oN“
.eciov taht htiw eb ot hsiw eht dna
.tesdaeh sih rednu morf rellortnoc eht ta dekool noediG
;rorrim eht ni was eh negotorp eht dekil eh taht dna
.semag rorroh dna sretoohs nosrep-tsrif
”.em ksa uoy fi ,trats ot ecalp doog a ekil sdnuoS
,lamron si egnahC
.snortap gnirehtag htiw dellif
,edutilos ni yppah eb dluoc eh eveileb ot nageb eh sraey eht revO
ti tsol natrapS .detniop noediG
;etilletas tnatsid a ekil tlef eH
,1241 rebmun ot yaw eht nO
seye yraew htiw nam a ,rorrim eht nI
”!era uoy ereht ,noediG ,yeH“
,nehctik eht otni deklaw eh ,ecaf sih gniyrd lewot retfA ”.tihsllub tahW
dnuora kool ot deunitnoc yehT .dias natrapS
.mih ta tuo eugnot sih kcuts
”.etunim a ni ereht eb ll’I ,doog sdnuoS
a morf tseuqer dneirf a
?od ot tnaw uoy od tahW
.god cihpromoporhtna na sa denruter dna dehsinav
.dne eht ni tuo now sdileye yvaeh dna nosaer tub
.dias noediG ”.hcum ytterP“
.yripxe fo etad a dah yrruF gnieb taht
”?he ,eman ruoy koot ydaerla ydobemoS
deddon lenap nottub eht ta tnanet A
”?orteM s’yadot taht si ,hhO
.hguorht llef eh sa nepo gnulf rood ehT
nuf gnivah saw eh taht timda ot detnaw mih fo traP
,parts tsirw eht dehcatta eH ”!og ew erehT“
”.siht dessim I .ecin s’tI
…lleW“ .denaorg noediG
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
;srood tnemtrapa derebmun eht deciton eh ,yaw sih nO
”.secaf ekam I nehw sregnif ym ta kooL
,siht ekil gnirolpxE
negotorp ehT .serutseg dnah tnereffid tuo deirt dna erutaerc eht deye eH
,nur ot detnaw eH
;meht ekil saw eh ecnO
”.macbew aiv uoy dediug tsuj I ,krow eht did uoY
.deksa natrapS ”?ti ekil uoy od woh ,haeY“
.dnuora radnelac eht denrut eH
”.esrow eht rof s’ti leef uoy tub
”.si ti kniht I ,haey
”?ypeerc gnieb modnaf eht no sklof redlo tuoba stsop esoht eciton reve uoY“ ”?tahw ekiL“
.tnew dna emac dlrow retfa dlrow
?yadot rof adnega eht s’tahw
og tel ton ot hsiw eht neewteb nrot tlef dna
,oS .elbadnatsrednU“
,rorrim a ,erutinruf emos saw erehT .’emoh‘
,efil fo erutan eht serolpxe ohw ,arDiK yb
.ni gnikcik enituor gnineve dlo emas eht
.roolf thgir eht detceles dna
,naeco krad ,ediw a ni degrembus dna deflugnE .retaw tih eH
.daeh sih koohs eh ,rehtruf thguoht eht gniusrup fo daetsni tub
.dnuora deppolf srae s’erutaerc ehT
deraeppa neercs gnidaol A .ezorf dlrow eht
”.tnereffid eb ot sgniht tnaw I tuB“ .aelp A
.flesmih ta dekool eH
,snoitpo eht otni tnew eH
”.oot ,uoy fo ecin ,llew
.niaga no ti nrut ot deirt dna deliaf dah taht rellortnoc eht ta dekool eH
rotcepsni eht sa reredrum eht dnif ot gniyrt ,rednatsyb a sa seulc rof gnikool saw rehtie eH
,thguoht eh ’....gniward otni kcab teg dluohs I
.eromyna citnehtua leef ton seod tI
.llaw eht no serutcip eht fo eno fo
?thgir ,yas yeht tahw s’tahT
.nosrep ni gniteem ot resolc gnihtemos
.em teg syawla snoitanosrepmi-nosleN ruoY .niw uoy ,yakO“
retcarahc a sedulcni yrots s'yadoT :gninraw tnetnoC
.ksed sih ot tnew eh dna ,ydaer saw aet
.roolf sih no pots a ot emac rotavele eht yllautnevE .yhcti gnileef
,secalp devom I dna efiw eht ecniS
,sdnoces ni pu detoob retupmoc ehT
,rorrim eht fo tnorf ni nwod tas eh
.sgel sih evom yldrah dluoc tub ,spetstoof eht fo noitcerid eht tsniaga nur
”?seno gnittif emos su dnif dna gnirolpxe otni thgir daeh s’teL
.gniees tpek eh dlrow eno saw erehT
,lla rof emulov eciov eht nwod denrut
”.flesym rof ratava retteb a dnif attog llits ,erom elttil a dnuora kool lliw I kniht I
”.ratava tluafed eht eb tsum tahT
detrats tneilc eht elihw dna no tesdaeh RV eht tup eH
”!og s’tel ,thgirlA“
,heH“ ”.yllaer elpmiS .yrettab eht ta tnioj redlos dloc a saw ti ,haeY“
.dehgual neht ,dehgis eH
.tuo gnah ot ecalp ecin a su dnif nac I fi ees dna daeha og nac I ,ti ta kool ot tnaw uoy fI“
,latrop retfa latrop os dna
”.worromot uoy eeS“ ”.od lliW“
?oot ,gnignahc taht saw tub
”.klat yrruf lacipytoerets siht gnisu ekil tsuJ
.sraey elbaresim net tsal eht ekil tsuj
,ydob dna sdnah sih ta gnikooL .negotorp eht
.mih ta kcab dekool enilriah gnidecer yldipar a dna
rab eeffoc nredom a fo noitaercer a ni flesmih dnuof noediG
.won hguorht gniog era sremocwen eht fo tol a tahw dniheb tfel ydaerla eW
?emoh uoy ,eno yls
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
1 traP ,arDiK yb
?eurt taht saw tub ,drusba sa tuo ti detniop syawla enoemos tsael tA
,deb ylenol a ni gniyL
dah eh tlef eH .egakcerw eht fo otohp eht ot gnulc eH .ot
”?riaf sdnuos ,mp6
,meht was I ,haeY“
.gninraey fo llup eht tlef eh
nibac eht ni pu tliub semuf ydob dna taews fo keer ehT ”.uoy knahT“
.yrt ot semag wef a detseggus sdlrow fo tsil ehT
.reh htiw wohs etirovaf reh hctaw dluow I fi em deksa ehS
.elihw doog a rof gnihgual tsuj saw dna
.erif esuoh a gnivlovni
,moor eht dnuora decaps ylesool erew sriahc htiw
selbat doow ynobE
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ereh mih del taht htap eht dna
”?og ot erehw aedi na evah uoy oD
.dnim sih ta dewang tbuod-fleS
.si ti mp6 ,yakO“
tahw ton ,mH“ .revo flesmih dekool eH
navinim nworb a fo
.ecalp fo tuo gnileeF“ ”?gnorw tneW“
.natrapS etisoppo taes a koot eh erehw ,selbat wol dna
.level rieht no sdik teem ot evah uoY“
”.dlrow taht ot su gnirb ll’ti
.tey tsuj ffo gniggol fo noitnetni on dah noediG
”.uoy stius adnik flow a fo noisrev detacitsemod ehT
”.uoy fo thguoht I esruoc fO
.truh ti taht eciov eht htiw eb ot detnaw eh yldab os dna og ot erehwon
.sdlrow rehto ot slatrop suoirav dna
.snrettap citarre ni dnuora gniog
flesmih deyojne noediG
”.rehtegot hcraes ew neht dna
?erutammi oot eb ti dluoW
sriahcmra gnikool elbatrofmoc erom htiw aera egnuol a ot retnuoc rab eht sediseb sriats eht dednecsa noediG
.dnuora denrut noediG ”?thgirla uoy erA“
.ot detnaw eh fi neve tegrof ton dluow eh woN
.natrapS denioj-er dna
.gnileef taht wonk I“
.mih ta delims rorrim eht fo edis rehto eht no negotorp ehT
,gnineve yadirF saw tI  2 fo
.eson sih gninrub ekoms fo hcnets eht ,dehguoc eh
.yks eht morf gnillaf noom ngierof a ekil saw noediG
”.yppah meht ekam em depleh uoY
.llaw a hguorht dehsams eh ,tsrif redluohS .yawa ti gnipeek
.sexof tuoba gnihtemos uoy llet em teL
.yrrow ot hguone ylrae eb dluow yadnoM
.ni dedaol natrapS dna detpecca eH
.dias natrapS ”.sdik gnivah ot deerga evah ton dluow I neht ,esac eht t’nerew taht fi ,em eveileB“
”.tuo enut dluoc I hsiw I sgniht fo tol a s’ereht ,lleW“
.snoisserpxe laicaf fo sdnik lla edam ratava s’natrapS woh devresbo noediG
,traeh sih ta gniggut gnirts revlis a ekiL
etorw eh radnelac-llaw a nO
”.sedir wef a retfa elats steg retsaocrellor yrevE
tsael ta ,fpmH‘ .ti detset ylkciuq dna tnioj redlos dloc elbissop a was eh tub
.tsixe ton did eh fi sa ,kcab eht ot noediG dehsup dna
;emoh llac ot ecalp a rof lufetarg dna tnereffid oN .wen dna gnuoy
”.gnihton naht retteb s’ti ,gnikcart ecaf on evah ew sa gnol sa tub
”rorriM eht fo ediS rehtO ehT“
;mih hcuot ton dluoc tI
”?ti t’nsi ,ygnirc si eman fo eciohc yM“ ”?haeY“
,liart on tfel spetstoof delffum sih
.dednal yeht erehw rof erac on htiw ,hcuoc eht otno esacfeirb dna taoc sih werht eh
,llah eht fo dne eht ta rood desolc eht dnoyeb morf sdrow
”?ecneirepxe RV
,dniheb morf mih decarbme gnihtemoS
]esuap trohS[ ”.od nac I gnihton s’erehT
,swor dnalb ni pu denil
.gnihcraes htrow s’ti nehT“
.erutam erom gnihtemos ot niaga eman ym egnahc lliw I“
,roolf eht ot dils noediG
.ti tuoba kniht ot tnaw yllaer t’nod I“ .deggurhs eH
thguoht hsiloof a saw tI .enola eb ot ton
…citnehtua gnieb dna era yeht erehw elpoep gniteeM“
,selcric ni dnuora gniog
,sdnah sih htiw gnihtemos gniod saw natrapS
.redlo gnitteg deedni er’eW“
.ti noitnem t’noD“
.taen s’taht ,em tisiv nac uoy yaw siht ,oS“
.sdneirf morf swen tnacifingis on saw ereht ,esiwekiL
.hguoht ,tsil ym no s’tI .tey toN“
”.sratava era llaw eht yb ereht revo slatsedep eht kniht I .era ew erehT“
.no ti denrut dna rehtegot kcab rellortnoc eht tup
”.niaga slergnoM hctaw ot evah yllaer ew ,ylsuoireS
,noitcelfer sih saw won eh
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”-ot tnaw t’nod I .diarfa ma I“
,dnuora delffuhs noediG dna
tsap rieht morf tneve citamuart a gnirebmemer
gnuoy llits gnieb thgin eht dna dnuof ratava na htiW
erif fo gnilkcarc eht raeh dluoc noediG
”?gnorw tnew sgniht nehw rednow em edam ti ,tsenoh eb ot tuB .yllufepoH“
”.em rof ti evas esaelp ,ratava flow retteb a dnif uoy fI“
I‘ .oot ,dlo kool ot nageb - anosruF sih
.ppa laicos ytilaer lautriv wen siht s’erehT
topkcaj gib ym saw efiw ym gniteeM
”.ecnahc a uoy evig lliw I ,neht thgirlA“
eht tsap ,tsrif kcaB .og tel eh dna
.tnelis oot saw tI
.enola gnileef tuoba natrapS dlot dah eH
,ruf kcalb dah erutaerc ehT
noitarolpxe fo yenruoj a no og ot dediced eh daetsnI
ot no dleh eh otohp eht ta dekool eH
.ti dnuora elcric gib a werd dna yadseuT otni
”?spup dna efiw eht era woH“
:taht tsuj gnieb rof speerc delebal erew seirruF redlo eht won netfo eroM
.ffo gol ot emit saw ti dnuof ratava na htiw dna etal saw tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,arDiK yb
.detaicerppa tlef noediG
.slliks laicos gnitsur reve fo tes a htiw mih tfel dah enola efil sih wenk noediG
.evoba gniliec ssalg a ot pu gniworg eert a htiw
.erif eht hguorht dehsup noediG .hguone dah d’eH
.srood nibac desolc eht fo tnorf ni demrof dworc a sa
,denepo srood ehT
,nori gniredlos a htiw tnioj eht detaeh-er eH
taht rebmemer attog tsuJ .swonk doG“
.ecafrus eht hguorht gniretlif
.sih saw dnekeew sihT
.ecnatpecca ,ecnedifnoc ,mlaC
.thguoht eH ’.xif ysae na s’ti
”.yadretsey htob degrahc I ,ytpme eb t’nac yrettab ehT
”?dexif ti tog uoy ees I .kciuq saw tahT“
.daeh sih koohs natrapS
”.niaga dlihc renni ym dnif em depleh sdik ym dna