a yb desolcne flesti saw tI
psag naht erom on od dluoc ehs
.llew sa sretrauq ruoy rof egnarra nac ew dna eciffo eht ot uoy teg s’teL .ti od ylbaborp lliw yad a smarg evif tub
.stbed reh raelc dluow taht sdnif fo tros eht ton tub
I dedlew fo edam saw etag ehT
.neetnac reh morf knird a koot dna
.gnihctiwt sreksihw ,tcere srae
.epytonehp kle eht fo aremihc a saw ehs dna
rexal neeb dah ytiruces nehw
.teknalb-pal sih htaeneb noitatiga ni gnihctiwt ,liat sih fo flah gniniamer eht ro
.naf s’retaeh eht fo enord tfos eht dna
.ssecca on dah sregnevacs hcihw ot yrenihcam yvaeh eriuqer netfo dluow dna
.dias asuL ”,thgirla m’I“
.tibah fo tuo llaw eht fo esab eht ta rotceted latem reh devaw ehs ,ereh dne-daed a evah dluow yeht yhw
.tuo uoy gid emoc ot enoyna tcepxe t’nod ,uoy no sespalloc gnihtemos dna-“ .reh draeh t’ndah eh fi sa deunitnoc esoom ehT
.niaga dna emit reh otni netaeb dah dlrow eht tcaf a
.noitardyhed morf neknurhs spil yb esrow edam sutcir gninekcis a yb demarf
tsim fo sffup edam
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,gnignevacs tuo srehto wef erew ereht hguohtlA
.detseggus asuL ”,nwod wols dluohs uoy ebyaM“
.liava on ot tub ,thgim reh lla htiw dellup dna ,seye reh tuhs
”.yrots bos eht em eraps uoy fi s’taht dnA“
,erofeb thgin eht dels reh deraperp dah ehS
.sdrawhtron dednert
,tiftuo eritne na
egrevnoc sevil rieht ekam ot deripsnoc evah srats eht dluohs ,neht ,yhW
,ecno ta mih dnuora kcab erew smra reh dna ,wolb a mih kcurts dah ehs fi sa
”.esimorp I“ .delims dna
.emit saw ti langis ot ezeeuqs a mih evag ehs litnu ,elihw a ecnelis ni rehtona eno dleh riap ehT
.eci revo klaw ot deen dluow ehs fi lufesu gnieb
.feiler emoclew a morf tub ,tnemesuma morf ton ,niaga derettit ehS
”?gniog er’uoy erehw wonk neve uoy oD“
”.ereht teg ew litnu pu dne ll’ew erehw wonk reven ew tuB“
?metsys rieht nihtiw krow ylirassecen ehs deen ,neht tuB
smra reh otni reh tpews ahsO ,taht tA ”.kO“
detpmet-flah dna luftsiw ,dias ehs
,efil nwo sti dah dah ti tub ,nials lamina na ylno saw tI
.hcamots kaew a gniretslob fo yaw a sah gniraer-dlihC
”,marg a stiderc neveS“
dedroffa suht pirg artxe eht
,rehtona ro dnik eno fo snasitra erew egalliv reh ni nemow eht lla tsomla tub
.stnatibahni eht fo sehtolc roodtuo yvaeh eht etadommocca ot gnivlehs emos dna ,senirugif yrovi
ssenisub reh tuoba tnew ehS
.tnedicca eht retfa raey elbirret
.ti ot rodo hcum ton saw ereht taht eerged eht ot esproc eht devreserp dah dloc ehT
fO“	       .ega na gnuoy os ta mih nopu emoc dah noitisnart eht taht etaf lli ylno saw tI
.dne eht ni tsum sgniht lla sa
.peels naht rehtar
,sserP lesaeW yb dehsilbup ”,sevaeL eht ni nwoD ecaF“ noitcelloc yrteop stI
,ksed a detamixorppa sexob nedoow htiw dekcats
tsartnoc prahs hcus ni eci eht tsniaga tuo doots ,der-yrrehc thgirb a ,doolb ehT
”,neT“ “-I os ,krow t’nac dnabsuh yM“
,depoh dah ehs sA
,nwod ecafrus eht morf gnitavacxE
.sekats hgih detseggus ti fo dnuos ehT
.ni saw ehs dna erom tnemom A
,ti dellac slacol eht sa ”,eciffo ehT“
a otni tsrif-ecaf deklaw ehs erofeb dnoces-tilps a
,tsap eht ni ardnut neeb dah aera sihT   ***   .htron
pirt eht fo gel taht gnihsinif no detsisni d’ehs
noitativac eht otni pmal s’renim reh denihs ehs ,gnihcuorC
,taht naht erom on tub
daor tpewsdniw ,nerrab eht sa htmraw fo dioved sa noisserpxe na ,neht dennirg eH
.sevitaler esolc neeb evah tsum yeht
,tnemelttes eritne eht ot noob a evorp dluow tI
,seot suoretxed reh fo esu lluf ekam ot reh dewolla raewtoof reh fo ngised eht dna
.tsac tnereffid a no nekat dah ytuaeb sti ,rehtaR
.yawa meht tpek rehtaew dloc eht tub
.semit retteb ni detnuom neeb dah yrenihcam erehw
emos gnisuoh sevocla owt sediseb knalb
.yaw rehtie tnasaelp ro kciuq neeb evah ton dluoc ti tub
,dniw eht otni tsim fo tfard tsal eno devaeh tsehc sih
”.emoh revir eht ekat dna taob a erih ll’I enod m’I nehW
.yaw siht tsol ees ot detcejed saw ehs eno
,dnah tfel sih desiar eH ”?esimorp uoY“
”.pmac ot naem uoy ,si taht ,sselnU
,ydob gnikahs ,liarf sih gnicarbme ,mih ot emac ehS
”?occabot ekat uoy oD“
,erifpmac a ediseb gnir a ni degnarra erew
.laveirter tiawa ot
.ecalp gnidih sti morf ,hcni gnigdurg yb hcni
.temleh a reh teg ot evah ot gniog erew yeht
.dnuorgevoba kcab deklats ehs
.ereh ton ,raey fo emit siht ton tub
.kcurt eht fo foor eht tsniaga daeh reh dekconk
,reh ta decnalg yehT
,eurt t’nsaw tahT
.guh lufrewop a deretsinimda dna
,od ot tahw fo erusnu
,moor rehtona ni dih ehs elihw
.flesmih erusaert emoceb dna
”.sregnif dah lla ’slamina‘ eseht tuB“
.rewsna eht wenk ehs deraef ehs hguoht
.rohtua yrots trohs gninniw-drawa dna
”?ereh eb I dluow ,yenom yna dah I fI“
,bmilc ot deen thgim ehS
erutarepmet tneibma ehT
.ehtaerb ot ria elttil suoicerp dna evom ot moor on htiw tub
,gnieb ti llacer reve dluoc ehs naht reteiuq saw ,ereht morf llorts trohs a ,aes ehT
reh rof gnitiaw pohskrow derettulc eht fo reh dednimer tI
,denrecnoc saw ehs sa raf os llew sa tsuj saw hcihw
,sdrawkcab spets wef a koot ehS
,sgnivas reh evreserp ot tnet reh pu gnittes deredisnoc evah thgim ehs remmus eht nI
kcor naht rehtar nezorf-imes saw hsart eht erehw ot hguone saw ti tub
,dlrow eht ni ycnerruc reh lla ,reh htiw occabot fo smarg ytfif
,daeh gnizoo dna dehsag a htiw kcub nworb ,nael a
,llits werg sbmil gnireviuq s’kcub eht
.tluser emas eht ot
,selop-metot ekil serutplucs erew edis rehtie no etag eht gniknalF
dels eht daolnu reh depleh ahsO sa
”.em dlot yeht tahw s’taht tsael tA“
.tleb sih no hcuop occabot lluf-flah dna efink a dah eh tub
.ereh ti evaeL“ ”.nug-ria na tsuJ“
selbat gnidlof fo riap A
,emit tsrif eht rof ecaf delevirhs eht was ehs woN
demra meht fo nezod a flah
,sesiurb sa krad dna htrae eht ot wol ,sduolc-mrotS
,deklaw yeht sA .meht
seye tuo-deggub s’ahsO yb detacidni enil eht dewollof asuL ”.ho hU“
,derevihs ehS .wons denetaerht
”?ko uoY“ .decniw dna
daeh reh gnitsujda elihw renroc a nrut ot deneppah ehS
:melborp eht was dna
.oot ,noitseuq eht fo tuo saw gnittauqs os
,dedda ehs ,seson prahs evah esoom taht gnirebmemer tuB
eveels-taoc reh no htuom reh depiw ehs ,htaerb reh thguac dah ehs retfA
,deye-ediw a degnahcxe meht fo owt ehT
,syawla sA  .eurt dloh
regnis ,teop ,elawD yb
.ekahs a daeh taerg sih evag
,devres yromem reh fi tuB
,noinapmoc tnelis sih dna god dlo eht dniheb ni llef dna
,stserof neergreve emoceb dah snialp nerraB
.erusiel ta niolrup dna ni kaens dluoc reh sa hcus lerriuqs elbmin a dna
gninnipS	       ”?eybdoog gniyas tuohtiw evael ot gniog uoy
.reisae gniggid eht edam tahT
.trap tsrow eht si pu pirt ehT
gnireffus erutuf fo snoitciderp reh ton ro rehtehw dna
spahrep dah ehs yadoT
.seye ysword reh ta depiw dna
,meht ta pu derats eH
,dloc morf trap ni
yawa llup reh dehctaw asuL
,serif gnitrats rof desu eb yeht dluoc ylno ton ecnis ,hgih saw dnameD
:tiftuo dereyal a
.egalliv reh ni kcab
”tsiM eht ni reviR ehT“
.sesnel eseht htiw evael reh tel t’ndluow drayparcs eht taht saw melborp ehT
”.seloh hcaor“ dellac-os eht gnikrow enoemos rof yllaicepse
”,lla retfa nwod wols dluohs I ebyaM“
.stoob ekil-nettim dna ,sevolg fo riap a no deppils ehS
.haeY“ ”?kniht uoy od ,hO“
”…enin uoy od ebyam dluoc I .detaehc tog uoy nehT“ .taht
.ydob eht gnitacirtxe fo ssecorp eht gnirud semit eerht evaeh-yrd flesreh tel ot gniggid pots ot dah ehs ,os nevE
.moc tod nozamA retsnom etaroproc morf elbaliava si
.dluoc ehs tseb sa ti derevoc dna
,ereh nwod tsael ta tuB
.krow dercas taht tsissa ot delleper oot
.daeh reh koohs asuL
.s’ekanselttar a ekil gnikahs liat
,ksud gnimoceb yad ekiL
”.em rof ssik a ikiM eviG
,hsif deird rof anaujiram dna occabot edart ot emac klof sa
retnuh-erusaert a eb ot desaec dah ohw
,hsaelnu ot tuoba neeb d’ehs sraet ekaf eht kcab dewollaws ehS ”!enoD“
”?enog eb uoy lliw gnol woH“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
dnuorg nezorf eht revo dehcnurc spetstoof reH
.ecafrus s’llifdnal eht no eb dluow ti ekil drah-
.dias ehs ”,tsevrah s’raey siht morf s’tI“
,enola meht fo owt eht neewteb lautir a
.meht decudorp llits taht
secaf euqsetorg dna
mih rof edam d’ehs dnab gniddew reppoc devarg eht denihs ereht hcihw nopu
niatrec saw ehs nehW
.deddon dna ,dias god eht ”,haeY“
wollahs erew gud yeht segassap eht dna
llems yzzuf dna tnrub fo tros a
,ria eht ni gnuh gof lanosaeS
,nepo slennut eht dleh taht smaeb troppus tfihsekam
,esnopser ni dnah reh desiar ehS
decniw dna tuhs seye sih dewercs eh ,taht
?ylimaf sih llac ,tahw ekiL“
,htuom sih no mih gnissik
.esolc a ot gniward saw htfif eht won dna enog dna emoc dah syad ruoF
.derettum ehs ”,krof rehtona tsuj ylbaborP“
.tluaf sih ton saw tnemaciderp rieht dna
,sessalg gniyfingam
,nepo llits seye neknus eht
.eciffus dluow elcihev ydruts yna tsom won
seloh dna sniats lio yb derram sroolf etercnoc dna ,tuhs dedlew won
.ysaeuq reh edam ecneserp erem stI
.nwad gnimoc eht fo tnetrop a ekil ,worrub krad eht ni gnidnilb tsomla saw eralg neddus ehT
.flesreh ot tsomla ecalp eht evah dluow asuL
,remmus dna gnirps eht nI
,suxelp ralos s’ahsO evoba tsuj
egduls yci fo spmulc tuo gnikcah
.daor eht ot kcab seye reh dediug dna regniferof dna bmuht reh neewteb nihc s’dneirf reh koot asuL
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,elawD yb
yenruoj gnol eht nigeb dna
”.elihw a dnuora gnah dluoc I“
,yas t’ndluoc ehs ,ni mih enod dah taht noitacoffus ro llihc saw ti rehtehW
”,asuL ,uoy pots t’nac I
.sgab citsalp kcalb fo llaw
.ydaerla meht fo nezod-ruof ssorca emoc evah tsum ehS
dna sten epor fo gniliec eht rednu
,saw ti dias yeht revetahw saw hcihw
.seldnah gnipocselet rieht dednetxe dna
ria llihc eht ni ropav otni desnednoc hgis reH
skcilk dnasuoht a rof ecalp ylno eht saw latipac eht ecnis ,ylppus trohs ni erew dnik yna fo sesneL
.yawa klaw s’ruoh na tsomla
citsalp fo xob a saw tI
.tnemeticxe suovren htiw citsaps ,dehsarht pit-liat s’asuL elihw kool yraw
,llor evitatnet a redluohs reh evag asuL
,taht ta pu dekrep ehS
.mrots eht ni tuo dettops dah asuL epahs eugav
.dias d’yeht ”,xat s’tI“
?snoops eht lla erew erehw neht
.ecnalg a reh deraps sa hcum os rehtien dna
.tresed elap a no senud ekil hsibbur derevoc-tsorf fo sdnuom eht
,eveels etihw ,yffup a ni mra na saw
ot nrael ot deen uoY“ .dias ahsO
.enoemos dellik t’ndah yeht niatrec neeb evah ton dluoc yeht
,dekcom ahsO ”?gnihtemos oD“
,reh ta nwod dellac sdraug eht fo eno
,sevooh htob htiw ladep ekarb eht no depmots ahsO ”!tuo kooL“ “-
2 fo 1 traP ,elawD yb
”,og ot tnaw ew erehw wonk eW“ ”?tahW“
gniraew eb dluow ehS
lacitsatnaf fo skcats
.reh detresed dah hcihw htaerb eht retfa
,sruc ynniks fo riap a yb tem saw ehs erofeb spets eerht klaw t’ndid ehS
,hguorht dessap ehs retfA
.rettal eht ylekil tsom
,rehtaew hcus ni levart ot derac wef dna tnemelttes yna morf raf erew yehT
”.tih ew tahw ees s’teL
.sparts eht tils ehs ,dnah ni efinK
”.noos peels emos teg tub ,emoh teg ot suoixna er’uoy wonk I .sknahT“
.dnif siht fo htrow eht ta sseug ot nigeb neve t’ndluoc ehS
,ruf eht fo kool hcir eht yB
snoitalupop sa seiretra ekil hguorht tuc sdaor
”,lufituaeb era
.neht ecnis remraw nworg dah dlrow eht tub
,erif rieht ediseb delcric srelbmag eht morf pu tnew sukcur fo rennam emos
***   .gnirps litnu tiaw yrgnuh
.esle gnihtemos rof rotceted latem eht edart ot emit saw tI
.remocwen eht ni naht emag rieht ni detseretni erom gnieb
,deirram ehs erofeb kcab ecirht ereh neeb dah asuL
,dias ehs ”,ton esruoc
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,htaerb reh gnidloh neeb dah ahsO
.gnillaf erofeb spets wef a naht erom nettog t’ndah mitciv ehT
,liat sih deciton ehs tuB
.gnuoy dna ywolliw rehto eht
.retaews eulb dna knip suoedih a ni esoom a yb dednetta
,yrotirret rieht fo noitrop siht rof tes erew nemhctaw owt ylnO
,siht ekil no tpek ti fI
?ksir tuohtiw emac gnivil fo trap tahw tub ,ksir a saw tI
.kcolb rednic fo edam erew seltsac fi ,erutainim ni eltsac a gnilbmeser nacibrab
.eil eht htiw yawa teg thgim ehs erehw ot hguone llew ti devreserp dah ehs tub ,t’nsaw tI
kcap reh otni htob deterces ehS
,hcum yb ton hguoht ,edistuo neeb evah dluow ti naht rehgih saw
.diarfa dna lufhctaw tub
.deirc ehs ”!thgit ooT“
sdnif reh yub dluow drayparcs eht ,daetsnI
,tnemetaba fo sngis on dewohs dna ydaerla yad lluf a rof drah nwod gnimoc neeb dah wons ehT .dehgual ahsO
,sruoh llams eht ni ecnatsid eht ni sthgil dettops gnivaH
.mih gnieerf krow ot tes ehS
.dnuos dekohc a edam asuL
ot esolc gnihtemos neeb evah dluow etar egnahcxe eht tub ,ti rof erawkooc dlo emos dedart dah ehs ,tcaf nI ”.neetfif diap I“
.ecalp lairub sih morf raeg sih fo tser eht detcartxe neht dna
.ni-evac a ni eid ot tuoba saw ehs fi gnirednow
,stekcop on dah sehtolc siH
.reh ot smra gnilbmert sih tuo dleh eh dna
.tnemom taht ta hctap hguor yllaicepse na no erew yehT
,ekil-yot kool erutinruf eht edam eh taht gib os saw eH
.derettit dna ,dedecnoc ahsO
,ahsO deman saw revird s’asuL .ypmub sa dna
.erom on gniees tub ,nepo gniniamer
,dias ehs ”,no daeL“
,ekoms elap fo psiw a gniliart hcae
,raey eht ni reilrae gnissim enog dah ohw rotavacxe eht detacol dah ehs ,oS
,tcnitsid saw tnecs eht
,deksa asuL ”?senob laminA“ ”.meht revo lla skram etib htiw senob fo tip a dnuof slortap eht fo enO .raey fo emit siht etarepsed teg yehT“
.regnad on ni saw ehs taht dna
.niaga kcip eht htiw dekcah dna ,rabworc reh htiw deirp dna
,dedart eb dluoc dna eulav dah hcihw smeti lla erew esehT .leets dna tnilf
.edis eno ot ffo gnikaerc dellor etag eht dna
,yraropmet naht erom reven dna
,noihsaf lausu eht deraeppa evah dluow tahw ni
,ecaf gnilims ehT
.redluohs dna tsehc reh hguorht tohs ynoga sa
.tcejbus taht dehcuot gnivah rof eroc eht ot lufesromer
tsrif taht ni seno revlis rieht lles ot decrof neeb d’yeht retfa
thgilnus fo secart tsrif eht nees dah ti hguoht sa
ll’uoy erus uoY“ .yawa dekool dna deredduhs asuL
.dnilb gnivird tnaem ti fi neve
.gnihtemos no thguac neeb evah tsum eH
.elacs cirtcele na no occabot eht tuo dehgiew eh sa dias esoom eht ”,netsiL“
.ebyam ,skeew fo elpuoc A“
”.tsrif ta taht thguoht yeht ,lleW“
,krow liated enif rof tol a od dluoc ssalg gniyfingam a dna
,gnikool ton erew sdraug eht taht dna
.noitulos eht tsuj dah ehs ,rettam oN
,dum ot sdaor eht denrut sniar eht nehw
.slirtson rieht otni
,yssolg dna yrd srosicni dewolley eht
.neercsdniw eht naht rehtar won reh ta gnikool saw ahsO ”?ydobyna seoD“
,flesreh gnileetS
.gnicreip dna hgih ,enihw oidar a tuo tnes tI
,erusaert eht dnuof ehs neht dnA
.drayparcs eht ot resolc dnuof eb ot gnisuoh retteb saw ereht neht
tnemom taht litnu tub
uoY“	       .noitceffa reh fo yhtrow sa dna
.erutuf ym ni niap s’ereht teb ll’I tub
tA	       ”.si ti sa tbed ni hguone peed er’eW
,gnilbmag sselerac no yawa segaw sih gnulf dah eh ekil t’nsaw tI
,eulav tekram eht fo tnecrep evif-ytnewt reh yap dluow yehT
,derrucco dah ni-evac eht nehw troppus a ot txen neeb dah
kcap reh dexiffa dah ehs hcihw ot dels llams eht elihw
asuL dedleiy evah dluow retaews sih ni nray fo tnuoma eht dna
,gnidneherpmocnu
,egnevacs dna ni emoc ot reh egrahc yeht did ylno toN
worrub rieht fo ytefas dna htmraw eht gnidart erofeb ssik tsal eno ikiM evig ot deppots ehS
.emit siht ytingid reh lles ot decrof eb t’ndluow ehs taht desaelp
.raey fo emit siht werc lluf a nur t’nod eW“
seloh fo lluf os erew serutcurts gniniamer eht fo tsoM
.sdnalg taews evah slerriuqs secalp wef eht fo eno
.moderob htiw degnit eciov enilucsam ,hguor a
retal tnemom a ,tuohs tcnitsidni na edam draug ehT
,lleW“	       ”.siht od ot evah
stekciht eht hguorht degdurt ehs
ecalp a morf emoc dah esion eht taht dediced ehs semit htoB
,erusaert wen reh htiw gnipacse ni sdeeccus asuL fi tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.htrow s’enutrof llams a
.kcab eht ni mih teg em pleH
.doots yeht hcihw nopu
.ekatrednu ot tuoba saw ehs tahw fo noitazilaer eht morf osla tub
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”tsiM eht ni reviR ehT“
,ecalp thgir eht dnuof dah ehs
no gnirednop doots ehs sA
.dnif dluoc ehs revetahw
,ees dluoc ehs esuohetag eht pota sdraug eerht erew erehT
.tuo tew eht peek ot htolclio fo htob ,ohcnop a dna sresuort fo riap rehtona neht
.flesreh rof eulav fo gnihtyna ekat ot dewolla t’nsaw ehs tub
.hcaorkcoc a ot nosirapmoc ediba t’ndluoc ehs
,esoper ot rogiv morf enog dah ti
.elahxe flesreh tel ehs did won ylno
gnihcaor er’uoy nehw raf oot tuo og uoy fI
.deksa kle eht ”?ko eb
.reh dniheb gnola deparcs
,deppans ehs ”,oN“	       “-worrob dluoc eW
.noossab desserped a ekil eciov a ni dias eh
htaeneb htrae erab eht gniguog sliar s’dels reh
.sih yb dewollof ,ffo kcab thgir sehtolc reh llup ot
,dneb a dnuora dehsinav kcurt eht litnu
.esora seussi revetahw otno
,yrareniti eht tcapmi taht tel t’ndah ehs tub
,yhtrae ,ysaerg
deralf slirtson suonrevac sih
,gel tneb a htiw riahc munimula na ot denoitom eH
”.eert a otni hsarc ew fi trofmoc fo eb lliw gnizihposolihp ruoy erus ton m’I“
.gnalc gnidnuoser a htiw reh dniheb dekcol dna demmals ti
.ytefas ni daor eht dessorc evah thgim eh dna
.deksa god dlo eht
.noziroh eht no gnikaerb tsuj
.tellaw a ni tif ot dednetni seno niht ,llams
.wolg ot tsomla demees ti taht
.egalliv reh ni sworrub rehto eht fo snoitacol eht dekram taht
,seot reh no
.deddon esoom ehT ”?stidnaB“
,dnah eerf reh htiw ssalg retuo evitcetorp eht gnitfiL
.kcat tnereffid a gnikat ,dias ehs ”,esaelP“
,tser eht naht mih fo trap a ssel on erew yehT
,kcurt eht fo tuo gnippetS
?gnirps eht ni uoy eeS“
levohs reh htiw depoocs ehS
,deooc eh ”,thgirla s’tI“
”?nug a evah uoy oD .retniw siht ereht ni raeppasid yug a dah ydaerla ev’eW
,tros luferac a neeb syawla dah eH
.werc noteleks a no gninnur erew yeht taht dessefnoc dah esoom eht tub
,sdnah reh epiw ot sevolg reh devomer dna ,gnitnap
.ecid fo riap a htiw snrut gnikat
.ytivac a otni kaerb ot tuoba saw ehs neht gniwonk
,sevolg krow yvaeh fo riap a
,llifdnal dna sniur yrotcaf eht ni yal
1 traP fo dnE ***   ”.oga emit gnol a ereh fo tuo deraelc eH kniht I ,oN“
.riah reh dekorts dna
,ecalp siht morf elihwhtrow gnihtemos egavlas ot emit tnacs reh tfel tahT
,enots ro htrae rehtie naht elbats ssel raf era spaeh egabrag tub
.hcamots reh deitpme dna ,denrut
.thgis fo tuo erehwemos ti dekcut dna tnemyap reh pu dexob dah esoom ehT
,rettam taht rof ,retal ro ,reilrae sdnoces wef A
ydob eht ssorca elbmuts esle enoemos evah ot nalp reh dednepu evah thgim ti
,remmus dna gnirps eht ni tnereffid saw tI
.laeppa thgim ehs mohw ot retibra on ,esruocer on dah ehs dna
,noitaroloc dna epahs elzzum ni seitiralimis rieht yb egduj oT
,ekoms enip sa esned
.riapsed fo slwoh htiw delgnimretni
sreyal suoiruc ni detalumucca hcihw skoobenohp gniyaced ,yggos dna
,rettib a evah dluow
.dniw eht fo tuo saw ehs
fo sbals desirpmoc llaw ehT
.smret eht erew esoht tub ,riaf t’nsaw tI
.lennut eht nwod yawa ylizal detaolf dna
,sretnuh-erusaert htiw nurrevo eb dluow ti
,elip eht otni rehtraf hcum
.revo tfel emos htiw
,dnim ni taht htiW
.yrovi dna lio laes
,deggut ehs txen nehW
,reed dliw a saw tI
.wons eht ni derettaps erog dewohs sthgildaeh eht erehw ot
s’regnevacs a fo egatnecrep tnacifingis a pu edam semitnetfo skroF
,yhpargoeg sti no dedneped ecnacifingis sti won
,ereht doots yeht sA
.elihw gnol a rof
.deb ot kcab og ot dediced dna
.ytilanif htiw dias esoom eht
saw daor tseraen ehT
eci fo hctap a no dils kcurt eht tub
.ekops kle eht nehw
,ria citcra gnittuc eht otni
,egnahc ot nageb sekirts reh fo dnuos ehT
.dne nepo eht ta delffuns eh sa detcartnoc dna
,swollef rieht ekil deritta dna
”.erofeb ereh neeb t’nevah I“
.lufituaeb gnieb desaec ton dah
,dnal yb pirt eht ekam ot sgod dna dels a dedeen evah dluow yeht erofeb erehW
sdnoces lareves roF
.knabwons a ni deirub-flah
edir reh teem dluow ehs erehT
,dehsurc gnieb morf mih peek ot noitativac a fo hguone demrof hcihw
,ti dereffo ehs nehw occabot fo gab eht koot eH
dnim reh fo eceip a ahsO evig ot tuoba saw dna tnorf eht sdrawot yaw reh edam dah ehS ”…netsil ,woN
,detfihs ria eht tnatsni gniteelf a roF
selcsum deneffits reh dehcterts ehs woN
htaerb reh elihw
,lio laes gninrub fo tnecs ehT
,krow ot emehcs reh roF
.saesuan os neeb t’ndah ehs fi dehgual evah dluow dna rehtegot deldnub lla skrof ytnewt dnuof ehS
.ecaf reh morf deniard elims ehT ”!lleh ,hO“
I“	       .denworf dna thgirpu doots ehS
”tsiM eht ni reviR ehT“
”.uoy tsoc lliw moor a hguoht ,yub ot ereh er’uoy fi egrahc oN .emac uoy yaw eht kcab og dna dnuora liat ruoy nrut nac uoy ro ,yad a stiderc ytfif s’tI“ .dehgis god ehT
.spil reh morf raf ton hgual a
)won srae eht ees dluoc ehs( tibbar ehT
.ssenkcisemoh fo gnap a htiw asuL kcurts hcihw tub
;emit eno ta seirotcaf fo riap a yb deniatsus nwot llams a neeb dah tI
ikiM dna ehs esle
.semit fo tseb eht ta efasnu
.snoitaitogen eht rof elbatrofmoc flesreh edam ehs os
netsil dna pots ot dah ehs eciwT
,tnacirbul losorea fo erutxim a
,srae reh ni gnidnuop traeH
.did nem rehto emos sa
,ytiliga lautcelletni niatrec a deriuqer
.seorht htaed sih neeb evah tsum tahw ni derettulf gelerof thgir siH
.sisahpme rof stigid sih gnivaw
.maeb nori dehsinrub a no deggans dah hcihw ,kcapkcab a gniraew saw tibbar eht
,dnuom eht fo gnitfihs dna gnikaerc suonimo eht ot
”.dray eht ni rehto hcae gnibbor elpoep tuohtiw elbuort hguone teg eW
?erutcnuj a enutropponi os ta
.riahcleehw sih morf ylbaffa gnilims ,flesreh ekil lerriuqs a ,ikiM was ehs
thgil gninrom yerg eht rof
:yojne esaelP    .ytiniffAruF no
,skeehc denepmad htiw mih derolpmi ehS ”!em evigroF“
.og t’ndluow uoy hsiw I tuB“
,mra sselefil eht depsarg ehs
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,won sraey rof dah ehs sa ,yctpurknab fo psuc eht no syawla gniviL
.dessik ehs sracs eht nevE
.detpurretni ehs ”,gnitavacxE“ “-
,wons dna dniw fo hsur eht tub dnuos on saw erehT
,dehsirevopmi eht rof hgih syawla erew sekats eht ,neht tuB
,sracs evisnapxe htiw saw ti hguoht degnahc
,sdileye dna srae sih
.sepytonehp rieht desseug evah ton dluoc ehs gnihtolc fo sreyal ynam os ni depparw dna dedooh lla
,erofeb tnemom a etuloser os ,traeh reH
hpmuirt fo sraor
,selicimod enola tel ,skaerbdniw sa enod evah t’ndluow yeht
.tiforp eht lla edam srenwo eht elihw krow eht lla did swollef reh dna ehs ,trohs nI
.gnilims morf peek ton dluoc ehs dna ,eno eurt a
,swerc llams rof reisae saw gnilennuT
ssenisub fo tuo enog dah airetefac ro erots a ebyaM
.detarobale kle eht
,tuo dils esproc eht
,htolc yerg fo spirts htiw dnuob erew selfir rieht nevE
.enog dna desrepsid naht nrob renoos on
,srepiw dleihsdniw eht fo gnikaerc eht
.tops thgir eht gnidnif fo rettam a ylno saw ti
,edam d’ehs eloh eht dnoyeb tsuj ,erehT
.detucortcele neeb d’ehs fi sa delzzarf ruf ,ydob reh ot elgna thgir a ta tuo kcuts liat reh dna dekcarc enips reH
”?yenom yna tog uoY“
.mrala na esiar dna
,detresed tub lla saw ecafrus tpewsdniw eht
,dehtoos saw eye dekcinap ,dnuor sih dna
,pohs riaper rac a neeb evah ecno tsum taht gnidliub a saw
seye eht ni tnemom a reh gnikool ,dias eh
,enod saw taht nehW
.tsop gnidart eht fo etag niam eht sdrawot dedaeh neht
,gnittup-ffo dnuof evah dluow tsom taht
.tsehc reh ot tsaf mih gnidloh
,ssap rehtona ti evag ehs ,suoiruC
,ecnef eht revo sesnel fo xob eht devaeh ehs
.eulav tekram eht fo retrauq a tuoba ta
.mra eht no reh deppalc dna
,noisluver suoicsnocnu ni yawa daeh reh werd ehS
.enod dah ecno yeht naht llew ssel desucof taht seye ro
ereW“	       .ecafrus eht ot pu gnidael pmar eht no gnitiaw ereht saw ti
.deb-kcurt eht morf kcap dna
.atarts lacigoloeg ekil
efil gniniard s’erutaerc emos fo llems nori ytsum eht gnitfaw
.kcen derit sih no poord daeh sih gnittel erofeb
,dnah sih detfil dna eye eht ni reh dekool eh woN
eson s’asuL tup evah dluow reh htiw ecaf ot ecaf gnidnatS
?ereh pu dedne dah erawrevlis rieht dna
,mirt ruf xuaf htiw akrap a dna trihs ,sresuort
.hteet devruc reh gnisopxe ,kcab dellup spil
.gniworrob erom oN“
,sdraug fo puorg rehtonA
,niaga nwod reh tes ahsO ”.yrroS“
ycneiciffe dna deeps htiw raeb ot thguorb eb dluoc taht ytilibixelf a
.nael erew semit nehw thguob eb t’ndluoc ti taht flesreh ot dneterp ton did ehs hguoht ,tuohtiw og ot tsael dekil ehs yruxul eht saw tI
,sraey eseht lla retfa nevE
,kcatta eht desserp dna delims ehS
,srood gnillor ediw htiw
,edarg eht no sdnepeD“
,esirprus ni gnipsag ,flesreh thguac dna pmal-
wols saw ti tub ,noitpo tsefas eht raf yb saw
,edirp reh derettab revewoH
tfarcidnah elacs-llams morf edisa yrtsudni ylno ehT
.smreb nehtrae ro
”?gnihtemos od ew t’ndluohS“
,deneziw dna trohs eno
def ikiM dna reh peek dluow ti tbuod on saw ereht dna
,teknalb neloow a dnuof ehS
hturt ni saw tub
”,uoy ezingocer t’nod I“
.gniggas liat dna srae ,deksa asuL
,leets sselniats dna reppoc morf rehtegot deceip
,nekorb gnihtoN“ .deksa ahsO
.tnedicca eht ot sknaht ,od reven dluoc ikiM dna ehs gnihtemos
***   ”.repmub wen a rof mih edart nac I ebyaM
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
lairub rof sniamer eht dehsaw dah retsis dna rehtom reh yaw eht
,os saw taht fi tuB
,tnemegnarra elbatiuqe na dellac evah dluow ehs tahw ton saw tahT
revetahw otni demmals dna
seirots sti fo erom dnif nac uoY
.sduht wolloh ekil erom gnimoceb
.desserd ehs sa slirtson reh fo sedisni eht detaoc
.ereh deurcca ehs seef revetahw ot noitidda ni emoh taob eht rof yap ot evah dluow taht dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy
.hctam eht tuo koohs dna
erats yrotasucca na htiw meht xif ot demees eye s’kcub daed ehT
knil niahc erew ti fo snoitces hguoht
,retemirep eht gnihctaw sdraug erew erehT
.selbaulav rof ydob eht dekcehc ehs ,tsriF
,ereh ecalp otni devom dna sgnidliub fo snoitadnuof eht morf tuc neeb evah ot dekool hcihw etercnoc
,diulf ciluardyh dna esaerg enocilis
.gnituocs reh rof txeterp a
srats otni detargetnisid noisiv fo dleif s’asuL ;mutnemom nwo rieht morf stlebtaes rieht otni dehcnerw erew sregnessap ehT
.sremaerts ekil ria sseltser eht ni deliart hcihw
,mih demalb reven dah ehs fi tuB
ecalp gnidih sti otni kcab esproc eht deffuts ehs
,srettil desiar dah meht fo htob eht tuB
.eurt neeb evah neve yam tI
.sdnif rieht ssecorp ot drayparcs a dexiffa dah stnediser eht hcihw ot
,ytirailimaf sti ni gnitrofmoc tey
,syenmihc gnidurtorp fo
kciw s’nretnal eht ot emalf tup ehs
.sriah etihw ,esned ni derevoc dnah a dna
.mih fo thgis eht ta dewaht
.leets teehs neewteb dehciwdnas smaeb-
daor eht ni spmuh eht flah taht tnaem thgieh suoulfrepus taht dna
.eriw rozar detsur fo slioc htiw deppot saw riaffa elohw ehT
,deid dah rehtaf reh nehw derebmemer ehS
tfird a otni dehsinav ti erehw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ti rof pu ekam ot hguone naht erom flesmih demalb eh neht
”,citamgarp oot er’uoY“
,nwod sloot reh tup ehS
,gnuws ehs sa llaw eht otni tib kcip ehT
taht ta dehgual eH ”!doG dooG“
kcip dna levohs reh deveirter ehs ,tik reh morF
,enim tip a fo rennam eht ni lairetam gnivomer
,kcor sa drah saw dnuorg eht dna won retniw saw ti tub
.pirt siht rehtona retfa eno meht gnidnif neeb d’ehs tub ,luah
,ebirt tibbar ro xof eht fo rebmem a neeb dah siht desseug ehs
,sllaw trid dah reyof ehT
.erom htrow erew ,esle gnihton fi ,snoopS