”?yawawots a rof kool ro ,werc ym ta loohcS yadnuS hcaerp ot ereh uoy ,yawynA
.edis dna kcab sih tsniaga ,tsehc s’retto eht ni gnivom ,htaerb s’niatpac eht leef dluoc nehS ”?ekil-drawkcab
,tnuag dna ,llat saw ffirehs dnuohdoolb ehT
,kcab sih no doow demraw-nus fo gnileef eht tuB .hcum t’nsaw tI
.feiler tnedive htiw tekcaj sih ffo deleep niatpac ehT ”.revir eht no t’nsaw I esuaC“
.dnim on eton gnorw a diap ti fi sa no tnew gnos eht tub
.dloh nwo sih revo lla sffirehs eht dewollof eH
yas ot esu dluow noreh eht lward enotonom emas eht ni ,oriaC dias
slleps lufwalnu lles ot gnikool nam-erujnoc ro hctiw tnargav adnik emos ylekil saw ohw etoyoc a
,mih ot txen dna mih htiw rellit eht no nwarb dna ydob gnisserp
.sepoh nehS sa ylhguoroht sa deraeppasid evah
.puc nit a ni knird ot gnimaets gnihtemos mih nevig d’enoemoS
”?ris ,ytirohtua ym ’ninoitseuq uoY“
”?ot nettog eh
.yawyna erom yna elbat eht no saw ytilibatcepser ekil kool t’ndid yltsenoh ti dna
.ksa ot flesmih thguorb terref eht ”?n’pac ,melborp a erehT“
reveF telracS eht tog uoy woh saw sroodtuo ria thgiN
”.taob eht no emoc ew nehw“
,smra sih gnitfihs ,sredluohs sih gnivom saw ,mih dniheb thgir saw niatpac eht neht tuB
”.em sepacse nam oN .t’now eh nA
”?owt ro thgin ylenol a fo ,kcommah a nirahs dnim t’ndluow eh ebyam epoh d’I dnA
,floWcaM boR yb
.pu gnittis ro daeh sih dniheb morf sdnah sih gnissorcnu htrow t’nsaw ti tub
.srewsna lufesu ylralucitrap
.nehS ,bmud t’nia I“
,detrons omluztiF ”,si eh esruoC“
.tsehc s’retto eht tsniaga kcab mih gnillup
,ruf kcab sih hguorht edils delahxe revir eht ytidimuh looc eht leef
.muelosuam ytpme na ni seohce etinarg ekil eciov a dah eh ,nekops d’eh woN
,htorb eht fo tser eht nwod deplug suirebiT
ni enuT .rettiwt no agemOJsulPamgiS@ yb slacov pukcab dna noitcudorp lacisuM derutaef hcihw
”.egarbmu sekat aM detnias ruoy erofA“
.hguone trohs syawla saw remmus dna
.derutnev eh ”,ecneralCcaM suirebiT ,hU“
,kced eht otno tpews sffirehs ehT ”.wonk d’I
.lamina sseltser a ekil kcod eht fo egde eht no ecap omluztiF niatpac gnihctaw ,kced eht no gnignuol gninrom eht fo tser eht tneps nehS
”,neht ,yrots eht uoy dlot ohw allef eht dnif ew nisoppuS“
tahW“ ”.ecalp rehtie seog ti fi ,nilevart er’yeht revir adnik tahw rednow attoG
,ruf gniyrd sih ni elbatrofmoc worg
.mih dnimer ot rehtob t’ndid omluztiF tub ,stnap no tup ot revaeb eht ot derrucco t’ndah llits yltnerappa tI .deksa niktiA
”.sseug I ,ysae ytterp
derucco reven sah ti mohw ot nam a fo ecnedifnoc eht htiw ,revaeb eht dennirg ”?haodnanehS rof trohS ?nehS ay llac ew yas tahw nehT“
,ffo mih tuc ffirrehs rehto eht ”,naem uoy od tahW“
,niatpac m’I dna ,ma I ,lleW“
.top eht ot gnihtolc fo elcitra na dedda enoemos nehw rethgual lareneg lanoisacco eht ro
,tsap dezeeuqs d’eh ragus elpam fo lerrab eht no weksa dekconk neeb dah hcihw
”,dluoc ebyam I sseug I“
”.taht fo niatrec ylthgir t’nia I“
,’npac eht htiw srepap
kaeb sih dnuora srehtaef sih deppuc gnilratS eht
,knalpgnag eht ffo deppets eh sa delbmurg gnilrats eht
eman wen a gnivah woh ees dluoc eh dna ,mih egaruocne ot tseb sti gniod saw yeksihw eht tuB
,dexaler terref eht oS
.fles’m laeppa eht neeS
em ’a daeha anaisiuoL ot steg tahw taob yreve dna
,yob gnuoy a saw I nehw lleW
,liat sih no kcab denael revaeb ehT
.reets ot uoy ot kool annog t’nia I tub ,namrevir a eb ot tnaem er’uoy foorp si tfiws no thguac uoy tcaF
,dennirg niktiA ”!nac eruS“
.ffo gnitsac nigeb ot werc eht rof deltsihw noreh neerg eht dna
”.ssentiw ym s’reviR“
,omluztiF muhamilaS suolehcA niatpaC dias ”,neht woN“
.maeb nedoow gnol eht ediseb moor edam retto ehT
.ti ni yeksihw hguor dah ti ekil detsat ,htorb fo dnik emoS
”!elihw gnol a rof ton tsaeL .enola ton tsaeL
,skool ehs naht reisae s’ehs ,dal ,nwod mlaC“
’,niatpac‘ sa fo kniht ot tseb sih gniod saw nehS ohw
,si ti revetahw r‘ loow r‘ niarg rieht pu daol
.sdoog delggums gnidih fo taobrevir a tcepsus thgim namwal ynnac a ecalp fo tros eht
.rethgit teknalb eht dehctulc terref ehT
.thgindooG s’enerI eht fo tnorf eht drawot derutseg retto ehT
,did ehs thguoht ehs sa kool a doog sa teg t’ndid ehs ebyam ,lleW“
emit txen
.ecalp rieht ni ydotsuc ot dednamer saw nos rieht oS
”?haodnanehS eht saw tsesolc eht sseug I“
,xaler dluoc eh llit daeh sih ni sdnoces eht gnitnuoc saw omluztiF ”,skeew ruof r’eerht tsael ta eb ot ekil s’tahT“
,dias omluztiF ”?yawrednu teg nac I naem taht seoD“
.semankcin yb ’niog htiw dloh t’ndid aP dna aM“
:srednef s’thgindooG s’enerI eht pu deluah niktiA dna eH ”.regnessap ruo ot ees s’teL“
namrevir a woN  .revir a ni dum ekil
,sehceerb sih otni kcab niktiA deklat eH
,reggidevarg a sa mirg ,derettum ffirehs rehto ehT ”,mih dellems I“
”,em esucxe ll’nemeltneg lacihposolihp uoy woN“
,dias d’eh ,thgin lufituaeb a eb annog saw tI
”.nehS ,draoba kcab s’enoyreve sa noos ffo tsac ot ydaer er’ew erus ekaM“
,demialcer eh pac htolc dna stnap eht ni
.edis eht revo sgel egnaro yltnarbiv llits tub delknirw sih delgnad
”?erehwyna teg yeht d’esle woh rO“ ,deggurhs niktiA
…sej annog t’nia I ,niktiA …t’nod I“ ”.hguone nialp nialp s’tahw ees nac I tuB
,deretsulf dna dehsulf dekool gnilrats ehT
,mleh eht ta oriaC ot pu deddon omluztiF ”.wonk t’ndluow I
.su fo nam a yna sa ylmrif revir eht ot gnoleb ll’eh ,grubskciV tih ew emit eht yb taht mur fo guj a regaw ll’I .ees dna tiaw yas I os
”,n’pac ,tib tsal taht tset ot regae m’I erus toN“
.dloh eht ni ylwolloh gnidnuos stoob yvaeh
dna deracs dna digirf saw daL“
.denepo gniht eritne eht tnemom a retfa dna
.lla ta meht dniheb seye yna dah wollef eht eveileb ot drah saw ti dna
,suirebiT rehtehw tuo dnif ot
”!yob ,on lleH ?tahW !oN ?tahW“
”.noisufnoc on eb ot ekil t’nia ereht os ,ereht morf s’draoba esle ydobon kniht t’noD“
,revo siht nikat
,kced eht no yal oot ti erofeb gnol ekat t’ndid ti dna sraey rof ograc gnitfil neeb hcae d’yeht tub
”?woleb s’eh spahreP“ ”.mih llems d’I“
!erehwon og mih nittel t’nia I ,dnah sih fo kcab eht n’retteb revir siht swonk oriaC“
,sgnul sih fo pot eht ta dewolleb neht ,dennirg revaeb eht
.knird ot woh swonk
”?neht ,aedi cisab eht tog uoy nokceR“
”.lla si ,ysaenu mees tsuj uoY“
s’erehW ?mih ksa dna“ ,smraerof s’niktiA no ruf hguor eht dekorts nehS
,eman wen sih ni dna
,gnorw elttil a tsuj tih dluow eno ,seton wef yrevE
.no gnittup otni mih deklat dah suirebiT stnap eht fo stekcop eht ni sdnah
”.rehtohcae ta waj si od ew lla dna ,thgin remmus eht yojne ot ereh tuo er’ew diaS
,etulf nit paehc a fo cisum teewsrettib erom ,resolc ehT
.das tib elttil a ton dna wols enut A
.rellit eht ta eno eht t’nia uoy dna niatpac eht s’taht eno eht tnia uoy ,ereh pu sallef eerht eht fo
,derewsna niatpac eht ”,neht no oG“
.kcod eht ot ffo eit dna srednef eht tuo yal ot mih dlot
,moor erom ekam ot flesmih detfihs ,delkcuhc niktiA
.ecnahc eht tog uoy revenehw yks nepo na rednu peels ot dah uoY
.retaw gnillems-yddum gnippird
.tlef ti gniyas larutan woh esirprus tnasaelp a ti t’nsaw dnA ”.niatpac eyA“
.ylraE htiw nosinu ni dehsinif oriaC dna omluztiF ”,namrevir a eb’t snaem ti tahw tuoba wonk uoy n’erom nettogroF“
”’nihton ro ,uoy pord …reven d’I
”.taht hguorht ruf rey hcaer t’nac nuS
.raeh ot saw ereht lla erew htaeneb revir eht fo ecnelis elbatrofmoc eht dna ,stekcirc fo dnuos tnatsid eht ,gnihtaerb s’niktiA esiwrehtO
.ti otni kcab naeL .taht ekiL“
”,enoyna n’retteb revir eht wonk uoy yas uoY“
,eybdoog erohs eht dib I ,teef ym ffo tsud daor eht dehsaw I .mialc sih edam d’revir eht ecno mih wollof tub pleh t'ndluoC .eman ym dellac revir eht ,yob gnuoy a saw I
”?ytilibatcepser teiuq ot ekaT
trop gib a ta ti lles ew neht
,ylsuoituac ,dias nehS ”,erew uoY“
.stoob fo riap wen a ni gnikaerb erew eh fi sa
.gniyrrac dna gnitfil eb tsuj ot devorp ti tuB
.ecneralCcaM suirebiT“ ”?erid os s’taht od eh d’tahw dnA“ ,pmar dloh eht no dekcats ograc eht tsap nemwal eht dediug eh sa noitasrevnoc eldi edam omluztiF ”?eman sih saw tahw ,retfa er’uoy allef sihT“
tarksum ,airtun ,sretto—werc ehT
.emit tsrif sih t’nerew ti fi sa ti hctac ot tseb sih did nehS
.epor a dessot namkcod eht erofeb ni hguone esolc meht delop
.daeherof sih dnif spil s’niktiA tlef nehS
.nwod gniyl elihw dluoc eh sa ytirohtua hcum sa htiw dias omluztiF ”.mih dnif annog t’nia yeht yhw si hcihW“ ”.detserra teg lla ew fi yap revirnwod nur a ekam ot draH
?eh t’nsaw ,pu tis mih ekam annog saw yllaer reedlik dlo ehT .deppans ylraE
,detfird thgindooG s’enerI ehT
.degnah eb ot tuoba erew uoy erus tneps
”.od klof ’o tol a n’retteb llitS
”?yawyna ,nehS deman eb dluow allef adnik tahW“
ngis yeht os ,revirnwod sdoog lles ot ’nikool yltsom er’yeht ,revirpu smraf eht ,ees“
.won llit pu gniklat eht eldnah gnilrats pmulp eht tel d’eh yhw ees ot ysae saw tI
,floWcaM boR yb
.ssenrettib ro noitasucca tuohtiw ,dias niktiA
rellit eht tsniaga ’nicarb er’uoy ekil ti no kniht ,uoy ’nilggob s’ti fI
,erom elttil a og tel omluztiF
.gnihtyna fo tuo deklat eb dluoc ohw nam fo dnik eht t’nsaw ylraelc dnuohdoolb eht tuB
.no gnillor eb tsum I ,em fo sekil eht rof t’nia hcus tuB .gnol gnitiaw ti peek t’noD .gnidne yppah ruoy s’ereht dnA .yad gniddew ruoy nopu tey gnicnad eb ll’ereht taht ees ll’uoY .yats ll’uoy erehw si ereh ,madam raed pots ruoy s’ereh lleW
.ecaep ni ograc reh daol ot thgindooG s’enerI eht gnivael dna dnuora gninrut otni deklat eb dluoc allef siht
,ralloc s’rehcaerp a ni amup a ,sllarevo ni eladsedylc gib a—
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.etsat gninrub eht ta decniw
,niatpac eht osla saw ereht ,meht fo eno rof tuB .rehtohcae dnA
,yvaeh ytterp saw eno tsal ehT
!emit evas dna won enotsdaeh ruoy tuo kcip llew sa thgiM
,slerrab os ro nezod a gnidaol retfa yhw saw hcihW
.esoprup on ot elbuort a ssem a’sti ,hguone eurt dna ,wonk ot erac t’nod I sgniht ’ninrael rehtob t’nod I kniht skloF
”.tsenoh eb ’t ,revir eht fo mottob eht no nipeels s’eh ylekil eroM
,kcommah eht fo dne eht revo kcuts teef sih
.deciton athgim uoy nokceR“ .dettimda niktiA
”gnitsalrevE sI gnoS ehT tuB
”.noitseuq ni evitiguf eht fo stuobaerehw eht ’ninoitseuq eugaelloc ym dna flesym tpec‘ ,gnihtyna ’ninoitseuq s’ydoboN“
.eb d’eh gnol woh ro gniod saw dnuohdoolb eht tahw retto eht naht aedi erom yna evah ot mees t’ndid gnilrats ehT
gnoL sI msitpaB ehT“
.rellit eht fo edis rehto eht ot dekcud retto ehT
.nam dlo ,tros eht fo gnihton enod I“
,revaeb eht ecaf ot kcab detsiwt nehS
,emeht emas eht evah seirots sih lla taht denrecnoc eb ot gninnigeb si ohw
hguohT .nemtaobrevir sa hcus snaiffur tnecedni fo ynapmoc eht ni nees eb sevlesmeht tel rO
,tnayoub dna wolloh ,epor ni depparw slerrab nedoow
,eirever evitatidem ,gniyaws yltneg a otni kcab knas noreh ehT
.troffe eht htrow t’nsaw siht dediced terref ehT
.ecivda lacidem reh ro ecneralCcaM .srM fo noinipo doog a fo hcum evah t’ndid eh gnidnif saw nehS tuB
,ecnatsid htiw tcnitsidni edam sadacic fo sdnuos eht
revir eht ,yob ,revir eht otnu ekat uoY(
”?revir a s’ti kniht uoy sekam
.pets a dessim d’eh fi sa tlef suirebiT
.deunitnoc dna deggurhs revaeb ehT
.derewsna retto eht ”,raelc llA“
”,evah I sa yas t’naC“
.tser eht atuo yap ruo su sevig dna ,sremraf eht ot kcab yenom eht ’a emos sdnes n’pac ,wohemos neht dnA !maertsnwod
.dias omluztiF ”!oga ruoh na taht lla’y dlot I“
”.no er’uoY“ .dekaorc oriaC
kcommah derahs rieht dellup dah revaeb ehT
”,n’pac ,tniop a tog s’nam dlO“
”.erom eno dda ot elba eb athguo
.retaw revir fo llems looc ehT
”gnitsalrevE sI gnoS ehT tuB
,kcen s’revaeb eht delzzun terref eht ”,neht lleW“
.etulf paehc fo dnik rehto emos ro ,eltsihw nit A
”,ereh pu t’nia eH“
”,gnitanicsaf sdnuos tahT“
.srevir naht rehto gnihtyna retfa deman eb thgim klof taht
,dedneffo ,tnangidni ,deyab dnuohdoolb eht ”!ereh t’nia eH“
,now eb ot mur fo sguj dna
ro ’sehcti kcen ym‘
”.enon semankcin yb og t’nod klof elbatcepser dna ,ylimaf elbatcepser a ’nieb ot yaw ruo no erew ew dias syawla yehT
”,yldnik uoy knaht nA“
”.mih ezingocer ton dna ecaf eht ni mih kool dluoc ffirehs a taht hcum oS
”,dal ,reh rof leef a uoy teg s’teL"
”?n’pac ,llew s’llA“ .emoh saw eH
,mih derussaer retto eht ”,han ,hO“
:eton ll’I hguoht“
,daeha ecafrus eht gnidaer fo ssenisub eht lla llits saw ereht yawyna dnA
”?uoy stius efil eht dnif uoy od woh ,hu ,dnA“
.puc sih otni derats dna decniw suirebiT ”…wonk t’nod I ,hO“
,redluohs s’niktiA no gnitser daeh sih dnuof nehS
,neve ,reisae ,dnahmraf a sa enod d’eh naht tnereffid oN
”?gnol taobrevir a gnikrow neeb
.retaw eht otni liar eht revo taps ylraE
.meht teem ot elbanu etiuq devorp yeht dna
…em no ninnalp t’nia uoy“ ,detatiseh nehS
emos woN .niaga ti dednem eh ,traeh ym ekorb eH .mih dewollof I .eman ym dellac revir eht
.seye desolc flah hguorht mih ta dekool
.ysae sgniht ekat I tub ,kcab em no teews me ’nivah pu dniw netfo t’noD
klofssenisub ekilhcus dna dnuoberohs eht tub trop edam yeht nehw tekcaj sih raew ot gnivah detah eH
?noitanitsed ruoy hcaer uoy nehw“
,nwod dehcaer omluztiF
.dehsulb nehS ”,n’pac ,ynnuf os s’ti sa wonk t’nod I“
gnoL sI msitpaB ehT“   yojne esaelP
,knab eht no gnihctaw doots dnuohdoolb eht tub
,kcab sih tsniaga tfihs ruf sih dna llor selcsum s’retto eht tlef nehS ”,trop og ot oS
.hteet dehcnelc hguorht god eht delworg
.mih dessot dah ,egrahc ni eb ot demees ohw ,retto gib eht teknalb hguor eht ni dehcnuh terref ehT
?ereht nieb dnim t’nod eh dna ,smra ym ni no teews m’I allef eht tog I ,erugif I
.dezeehw ylraE ”!emit siht ti ni su dednal yllaer uoY“
?I t’nod ,uoy tog I“ ”?yfmoc uoY“
.moc.yrrufos.flowcam-
.taht enod d’eh nehw derednow
.nethgit mih no pirg s’niktiA tlef nehS
.rellit gnol eht no decnalab thgiew
,nillup s’tnerruc ,dedaol s’ehs“
,draob nemwal eht tel ot
.dnas ro tlis fo knab a tnaem selppir tnerruc-ssorc eht ,skcor ro sgol degrembus tnaem sevaw gnidnats eht woh gniees
”,hguoht ,dnuorga su nur annaw t’nod yllaer I“
.t’ndid ti fi sa gnilrats eht dias
.flesruoy rof ees ot emoclew n’erom er’uoy ,eno tog I kniht uoy fi os ,syawawots htiw dloh t’nod I“
”.uoy wohs ll’I dna pirg a ekaT“
”?epacse eh d’woH“
.dehgual retto eht
?tekcar hcum os gnikam eb ot meht rof“
.lla na mih retfa sffirehs tog s’eh tcaf a ref wonk eW“
.smraf esrevid no rerobal yaD
.tsiwt a rednef nedoow eht fo pot eht evag
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
gnoL sI msitpaB ehT“
!esruoc fo ,delttes era stbed eht llit ylnO
”.yad eht ref em gnirih otni remraf emos klat ot niyrt saw eh fi rO
”,dnatsrednu t’nod I“
.tcejbus taht no yas ot saw ereht lla eb ot demees hcihW
?eh t'nia ,revir eht ot yawanur rehtona tsuj s’eH
doolb dna hself nwo rieht evael
,gnieelf si eh hcihw morf sgniht eht dna
.gniht nmad eht evom ot desoppus saw eh woh ees t’ndluoc terref eht ti dnuora smra sih htiw neve dna
gnineve eht dneps terref a dehctaw retto ehT
knab rehtie no yb deppils taht elim yreve dnA
,ffirehs a naht rehcaerp a ekil erom desserd eH
).oot uoy ekat ll’ew neht dna ,yob ,ograc dna sdoog ruoy ekat
,niaga elbatrofmoc flesmih edam
”?thgir ,revir a raen evil attog s’enoyreve ,lleW“ ”?revir tahW“
,nisufnoc teg ti t’noD“ ”.trop og uoy“
.don revaeb eht tlef eH ”?mih no teews“
neeb dah eh ohw fo tsohg eht dna
.namrevir a ekam reven dluow eh dlot dna duarf a sa desopxe eb d’eh ,ylbaresim liaf d’eh ,krow drah ylgniyortsed-luos ,gnihsurc-kcab ,gnikaerb-enob eb d’ti diarfa saw eh ,ti tuoba deklat—
,namrevir tseraen ehT ”!niktiA“
nrevat eht ot resieW tnes eh llit sruoh elpuoc a rof detterf eh yltsom tub—
flesmih detcerroc eh ,werc eht FO TSER eht—
,ylleb s’revaeb eht no daeh sih fo kcab eht
”?nokcer ey’d lleh eht woH“
.yawa dehsaw dah esle lla ,em peek ot eciohc on
.athguo namrevir yrevE .lla si
”!nwod secirp ym skconk
”:em retfa wollof dna netsil a eviG“
’.su no nwod gniraeb odanrot a s’ereht‘
.ti fo hcum sa t’nsaw ereht esuaceb
.kcahskooc sih otni kcab
,did eh sa dias omluztiF ”,oriaC“
.dias evah dluow rehtom s’ecneralCcaM suirebiT tahw hguone llew wenk nehS
”,niatpaC ,yrassecen yltcirts ti sI“  )nam a uoy sekam
.deilper omluztiF ”,eno no nroB“
,kcab erab ot tsehc erab
skcommah deipucconu yna EVAH t’ndid
.ti ot desu teg uoY“
”.retfa itannicniC neht
”.ereh ykcirt tnia revir eht dna
.thgindooG s’enerI eht dna mih neewteb teg ot ecnahc eht sffirehs gnikrul yna evig ot tnaw t’ndid eH .enog t’ndah nehS
.taht fo nosaer eht ees ot ylekil eb t’nthgim wollef gnuoy a degdelwonkca omluztiF .htuoy fo yllof eht ta ylevarg daeh derehtaef sih koohs ffirehs ehT
”.sihpmeM neve ebyam ,ellivsiuoL llit ti gnitteg t'nia ylbaborp ew
,tsenrae yldaed ni saw ecaf s’revaeB eht ”,lleW“
”.kcommah nmad ruoy ot teg ,emos neht n’thgin a n’yad a pu neeb uoy ,oriaC“
.elab a ro lerrab a fo flah rehto eht htiw knalp eht nwod sdrawkcab klaw ot allef a sdeen allef a nehw retfihs a fo lleh a s’eh dna
.llits ylluferac swap sih dna dessorc smra sih tpek omluztiF muhamilaS suolehcA niatpaC ”?taob ym no toof tes eh kniht uoy sekam tahw dnA“
.namrevir a em edam dna rellit a em dednah eH
?enod krow yna teg llits dna sehtolc deggolretaw ni miws ot nam a tcepxe uoy“
.gnos s’revir eht sgnis eh ,sdrow eht nrael ot deen on sah eH .gnol thgin lla gnignis s’eh ,gnis ot woh swonk namrevir A .lla ta peels on dnif nac eh kcommah gnillor sih ni dnA .lwarb nac namrevir A
”?stnempoleved yna era ereht esac nI
,ti nees t’ndah terref eht neht thgindooG s’enerI eht no toof tes dah nehS ecnis ecno neve rellit eht fo og tel dah eh fi ohw ,noreh neerg ehT
.foor kcahskooc eht ot pu mih dellup dna
klof elbatcepser yltnerappA
.kool prahs a mih evag retto ehT
.teknalb a ni depparw
...t’ndluoc I ,naem I
ybressap htiw noitasrevnoc a pu kcurts niatpac eht semit elpuoc A
?trihs a tuohtiw dna—
.yeksihw yletinifed ,puY
.rellit eht no gninael noreh eht dias
sredluohs sih ot hguone esolc
”.erom snezod ees ll’ew dna mih ekil snezod nees eW
?yeht t’ndid ,egrahc ni saw ohw llet ot yaw emos evah ot dah
.em ot netsil seJ“
.loof a t’nia allef siht dnA“ ”…esoppus I“
tuo ekam tsuj dluoc nehS ,deyalp eh sa rellit eht no swoble sih gninael yb gnireets llits yllacinhcet
…uoy evah ,niatpaC ,ereht oS“
,reddal eht fo pot eht ot tog terref eht nehw ,tsirw eht yb nehS deppirg niatpac eht
.eciov ’nignis hguone doog a tog I dlot neeb I“ ,nehS dias ”,lleW“
,noisserpxe s’revaeb eht yb gnigduj ,ton erew esehT
,mih gnihcuot yllautca fo retteb thguoht hguoht
,foor kcahskooc eht gnillac no detsisni eh tahw saw hcihw ’,kced reppu‘ eht fo egde eht no tas kooc dlo ehT
.niaga revir eht no saw eH
”,did I“ .deksa omluztiF
,edis eht ot dils dna
”.pu semoc dniwdaeh a n’fi evif ,yawa syad ruof s’taht dnA“
.sdrac yalp ro ,raews ro ,knird ro ,ekoms rO
”.lessev siht draob mih was ylraelc ehs dias tnamrofni ruO“
?ti no yal dna teknalb eht pord uoy fi retsaf yrd ll’uoy wonk uoY“
,eciov nignis doog a evah d’eh nokcer d’I“
”?boj eht fo trap taht em ’ninrael yb trats ew ’nisoppuS
.deyalp yltrepxeni
”!puos fo puc a nam a nivig ref em no nwod emoc annog t’nia wal eht esuaceB“ ”?egassap mih nivig morf tnereffid taht si woH“
,kcilc a saw erehT
.eid I yad eht litnu namrevir a eb lliw I dnA
?ytirohtua ylniatpac naht erom rettam lla esoht t’ndid
.thgindoog fo daetsni dias oriaC tahw yltnerappa saw
,lleh ro nevaeh ot pirt eht nikam er’yeht elihw ,deid reve s’ohw enoyrevE
.serifpmac lla saw ereht pu yaW ykliM eht woh tuoba yrots a saw ereht dias“ ,desum niktiA ”,etampihs a dah ecno I“
.flesmih rohtua eht yb daer
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT
.gnidaolnu eht ,gnidaol eht fo diarfa neeb d’eH
,sdnah gnignahc snottub dna seinnep fo gnilgnij eht revo erows enoemos nehw saw elbidua erew yeht emit ylno ehT
,lepal sih no egdab eht detsujda gnilrats eht
?revir eht tuoba sgniht tseb eht lla piks ot dah uoy tnaem ti fi ytirohtua ylnaitpac fo tniop eht saw tahW
”.erehwemos ereht pu erifpmac a ta“
?eriter ot epoh uoy erofeb gnol woh ,em lleT“
ll’eW( .uoy rof ecaps emos devas ev’ew ,yob ,yrruh a ni er’uoy nehw dnA .oot yeksihw ro niarg ruoy ,sarfassas ro tlas ruoy ekat ll’eW .dlog ekat dna ,revlis ekat ,selab nottoc ,nori ,rebmul ekat ll’eW :dloh t’nac staobrevir taht niyrrac sdeen gniht on tnia woN  .htab a ekat ot dnuob dna ,draobrevo dedaeh eb ll’yeht roF ,htarw s’revir eht ecaf lliw namrevir a taehc ohw esoht dnA .eraf ysae ruoy yap dna ,namrevir ruoy ot netsil tsuJ erehwyna uoy ekat nac eh revir eht no er’uoy nehw woN
,reddal eht nwod deltsub reedlik ehT
,hU“ ”?ay llac am rey d’tahW .lufhtuom a s’taht ,lleW“
snolemretaw gnitae dna taht ,llew—
,esruc a htiw elop gnihsif sih deppord ,airtun a
”.deen ni luos a yawa nrut nos reh hctaw dna nwod kool annog t’nia nevaeh ni eromineF aM detniaS
.dam saw eh fi ,ecneralCcaM .rM rO .suirebiT“
”.enim teg I sa gnol os erac yllaer t’nod ,woh onnud I
thgindooG s’enerI eht esuaceb yltsom dna tnenamrep yllacitcarp htob saw
,nalp s’revir eht sawt tub ,yawa nar I yas dluow
.omluztiF ta deralg ,desuap dnuohdoolb eht ”,t’ndid eH“
,ellivsyaM s’tI .neht lleW“
werc eht yaw eht morF
,gniliar eht yb gnittis saw flesmih dal ehT
,resieW saw ti derebmemer yllanif eh tub redrah saw eman esohw ,tarksum eht dna ,hctaN ,airtun eht woh ,hguoht ,ylluferac dehctaw eH
,taob ym no erew eh fI“
.gnos tcesni tneconni ,tnatsid fo dnuos ehT
”,n’pac ,wonk d’uoy depoh a-
,ffo tekcaj s’niatpac yvaeh eht leep dluoc eh nehT
.remmiws gnorts a saw eh fi ,won yb erohs ykcutneK eht no eb dluoC
?mih rof lausunu saw taht taht ton ,lla ta gnihton gniraew naiffur siht htiw dnA ?seohs rO
”?revir eht fo eman eht s’tahw
tiforp s’htnom a deregaw ev’dluow omluztiF enola neeb d’eh fi dna
”!pihs eht no erehwon mih llems t’nac I“ ”?ereh t’nia eh“
.ruf sih fo segde eht ta leef ylerab ot
.msacras sih dna drib eht nmaD
,terref a delwarc tuO
,foor kcahskooc eht pota tub ,ssenkrad eht ni elbisivni tsomla saw eH
.srats eht ta dekool dna
,yvaeh sa tuoba dna ,eert elohw a fo htgnel eht ylisae saw rellit ehT
.sselemoh dna yrgnuh
”.reh tnaw uoy erehw reh tup ll’tnerruc a otni syawedis reh edils tsuj uoy ,retaw eht hguorht taob a hsup t’nod uoY .thgiew ruoy htiw reets uoy ,smra ruoy htiw reets t’nod uoY .pu uoy dloh rellit eht teL
.suirebiT ot kcab denrut niktiA .sehtolc gnippos sih ffo pirts ot yawa deklats ,mih derongi airtuN ehT ”!hctaN yrroS“
,aedi doog a saw siht erus t’nsaw eh woh tuoba trap eht yas dluoc nehS erofeb ,dias omluztiF niatpaC ”.ot tuoba er’uoy ,lleW“ .derewsna nehS
d’I“ ”?trop txen ruo s’tahw“
,etal fo ,krow fo stib wen ynam lufrewop a tnrael I“ ,dias eh
.eno taht htiw smret ot emoc ot gniyrt eb ot demees eH
thgin sselpeels dna deifirret a retfa loag fo tuo uoy sluah ffirehs revetahw ot ti evael yeht
”!ti yojne su tel dna pu tuhs“
,woh wonk athguo tsuj uoY
”.teef ruoy htiw taob eht ’nihsup dna
”?puos taht mih evig uoY“
”,dluow uoy denokceR“ .derewsna terref eht ”,niatpac ,os nokceR“
.kcahskooc eht dniheb pets ot denrut retto eht llit
,wal eht morf nur eht no enoemos rof lufesu eb thgim
.niaga gnihsulb flesmih tlef terref ehT
.dnuof nehS ,esnes erom ekam ti edam tahT
.ti hctac ot rellit eht fo htgnel eht nwod gnirats ysub oot saw nehS
,ekila gnihton dekool yeht hguoht ,demialc yeht srehtorb ,sufuR dna nevS—
,retto eht ,itannicniC ni dekcod yeht nehW  .naelc uoy hsaw d’revir eht namrevir a erew uoy fi tuB .nees eb ot tif ton dna won ytrid lla era sehtolc enif ruoY .kced eht nopu rat s’ereht ,knabrevir eht nopu dum s’erehT .pets uoy erehw won erac ekat ,nemeltneg enif ,pots ruoy s’ereh lleW
.ot sdeen n’pac eht n’fi ,wolleb ot ysae si sa uoy rof eman a htiw pu emoc  athguo ew ,lleW“
denrael dah yllanif nehS seman esohw sretto nruticat owt eht dna ylraE dna hctaN ,kced eht fo dne rehto eht nO
.suoicipsus ,derewsna reedllik eht ”…seY“
.rewsna ot gnivah morf retto eht gnivas dna
dah ehs tuB yal I erehw em tfel evd’ehs etanutrof erom ro resiw fI edisni em derevocsid dna egakcerw eht derrits rehtom yM ediw dedoolf revir eht ybab a saw I nehw lleW :dloh eht otni setarc dna slerrab eht gnas yeht sa tooferab dna sseltrihs detaews—
,ti rof nur a ekam ot
,ylleb sih no sdnah sih dedlof ,kcab yal retto eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
?retrohs gnihtyna tog uoY“
erus ,ynnuf eb d’gniyl thguoht sej ehs ro ,yenom drawer eht detnaw ehs ro
.meht fo enon ni tnaem eh tahw dnif dluoc tub ,repsihw dehsuh a ni slained tnereffid evif ro ruof detrats dna deppots nehS
,sessalg krad dnuor yltcefrep erow
nehw roF  .revir eht erofeb
.yrd ot pu sehtolc dekaos s’terref eht gnignah saw niktiA
”gnitsalrevE sI gnoS ehT tuB
,ria eht ni ylregae eson a hguorht ,egrid a ekil ,decnuonorp dnuohdoolb eht
”.won yb ,hguone llew ti ekil I epoh d’I“
.thgil nretnal yb sdrac gniyalp erew—
,tsehc s’terref eht no sdnah s’revaeb eht
,deniap erew seye s’gnilrats eht
”?ycnecedni fo etats a hcus ni eb ot meht rof dnA
.revaeb eht ta sreggad gniralg dna tew gnippird ,decafruser dna
”,slley tsuj eh ,em stnaw n’pac eht nehw …ekiL
,pirt eht fo gel siht ,gnihtyna dedaolnu reven tsomla yeht denialpxe niktiA
?yeht t’nia ’nilevart er’yehT“ .deksa nehS
.emit driht eht rof selab loow fo elip a dniheb dereep dnuohdoolb eht sa gnilrats eht dehgis
”?yeht od ,nosaer ees reven elpoep gnuoy tuB
”,draobrats kcab og ot dnA“
.doow htooms eht ot sdnah sih tes nehS
,htnom tsal siht eud dellac yldetcepxenu erew“
.oriaC detcejretni ”,dluow yeht seY“
,yawa dehsaw yleritne noos saw nrecnoc yratnemom s’nehS os dna
,tnerruc eht ekat ot kcod eht ffo
.namrevir a dluohs rehtien os yrruh t’nod revir eht
,htiw rehtob t’ndid eh trihs eht tuohtiw
,redluohs sih no dnah rehto
,ecaf rieht ot swen fo tros siht nik rieht llet neve t’nod
.tohsrae fo tuo saw noreh eht dnoces eht denihw terref eht
.n’pac eht no teews ’nieb pots ot uoy ksa annog t’niA
.leets elbadnebnu fo lla erew senob eht fi tub senob dna niks
.retaw teews dna doow nrow-nus dna taews ekil dellems eH
”?eb ti d’esle tahW
.gnilrats eht dereffo
”?uoy htiw od annog ew er’lleh eht“
”,n’pac eht no teews rey dnA“
.pu dekool eh nehw gniyas saw niktiA ”,hguone llew uoy stius nehS ekil leef I“ !semankcin on yletulosba tuB .enif lla s’tahT
thgin eht no eniltuo sselrats eht
thgindooG s’enerI eht delop werc eht sa tuohs ot
,trop otni teg ot emit s’ti fi selop dna srao eht ta kciuq eb d’eh
edisa deppets omluztiF niatpaC ”,’niyas tsuj m’I
,htaeneb taob eht fo yaws eltneg eht
?ti tog ,yaw rehto eht seog dne tnorf eht snaem hcihW .sehsup ,retaw eht ni ,dne kcab eht yaw revetahw nrut ll’ehs woN“
”-ev’I dna uoy n’regnol thgindooG s’enerI eht no ’nippihs neeb I ,ynnos ,syawrevir tuoba em erutcel uoy t’noD“
”.nihton evorp t’nod tahT“ ”.taef naem on
.galf a ekil ria eht otni sehtolc s’suirebiT fo tsal eht deluah eh sa ,yllufreehc ,dias revaeb ehT
allef a no teews teg I“
,nevo hctud eht fo tuo dellup dah ylraE stiucsib fo hctab eht fo llems eht
.rehtegot thgit meht dleh kcommah eht erehw
.flowcam-bor ta yrteop dna seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.niatpaC eht saw taht
.thgin eht rof pots yeht nehw me sekam
.traped dluoc yeht os kcab enoyreve hctef ot
,srats fo duolc depahs-revir eht ta dnah a devaw niktiA ”,eurt s’yrots eht ’nimussA“
).erocs rehton‘ rof moor s’ereht ,nemrevir ynam revewoH( .erom rof moor syawla s’ereht ,nemrevir ynam revewoh tuB ,erohw a s’eh uoy llet ll’yeht ,smaerts gnilbbab eht ,sekal digirf ehT .niaga ni thgir pmuj nac yeht deb sih evael yeht hcum revewoH .nem ynam devol s’eh rof revir eht ekil ma I woN
,1 traP ,floWcaM boR yb
.feiler ni revihs
.sthguoht sih detpurretni dnuos rehtona nehw ,yas ot ,gnihtyna fi ,tahw erugif ot gniyrt saw nehS
?knab etisoppo eht rof muws ,ffo evod a’thgim eH“
grubskciV tuoba hcum oot deklat dah enoemos fi derednow taht eno ,neht kool ytliug ,prahs a nehS tohs omluztiF fi dnA ”.lla si ,ecitnerp a neeb ylerab I erof elcitra eniuneg eht atni em nrut ot yrruh a ni demees tsuJ“
”,snoitagilbo laicnanif yrdnus ’stnerap siH
.flesmih rellit eht hcaer ot nehS dnuora depparw smra siH
”.nizitpab rieht rof revir eht ot emoc ot wonk sklof dnuoberohs neve ,yhW“
,reedllik eht ta denworf omluztiF
”.oot ,em no teews tib a nitteg ot yaw rey dnif nac uoy ebyam tuB
,daeha retaw eht ssorca snoitcelfer ekil gniyalp seye
,ylnameltneg eb ot tog ,taoc nmad eht gniraew llits ,on tub ,noitartsurf ni decnad evah dluoc omluztiF ”,esoppus I“
”!reciffo ,tsisni uoy n’fi tub“
.gniliar wob eht dna enilsehtolc eht neewteb ffo ti deit ,kced eht no pu—
.emos uoy edausrep ebyam ot ecnahc a em seviG“ .delkcuhc niktiA
,teef sih ot flesmih dellup ylraE
,ruf sih fo tuo retawrevir koohs dna dnah eno htiw gniliar eht revo flesmih deluah revaeb a sa yllacirtaeht seye sih detreva eh ”,wollef taht ,yhW“
.derrits pitliat sih ylnO
sessalg krad hguorht omluztiF otni gninrub erats lufelab
”?noitacude sih no trats tneced a ekam ot tneiciffus eb athguo revir eht fo syad ,evif ebyam ,ruof gnivah dnA“
,revaeb a morf stonk eit ot gninrael
,yawa klaw ot denrut gnilrats ehT
.rewsna na rehtegot tup dluoc nehS erofeb keehc s’terref eht otni ecnelis dekorts
”?eh si ,erehwon niog t’nia oriaC ?uoy era
.denrecnoc erew yeht sa raf sa ,dlrow eht ni sgniht wef yrev neeb evah yrev thgim ereht ,thgin eht fo tser eht rof dnA .teiuq ,tcaf ni ,erew yeht nehT
!lla ta diap eb reven dluow tbed eht neht rof ,nosirp s’rotbed ot meht gnidnes ni esnes on eb d’ereht was etartsigam eht ,yllarutaN
’nibac eht‘ dellac yeht sretawdaeh ippississiM eht pu erehwemos morf
,yrruh on saw ereht ,on :lipup sih derussaer tsuj retto eht oS
,dnopser ti tlef eh ylsuolucarim dna ,rellit eht no thgiew sih gnah mih edam ,mih denael ,sredluohs s’nehS tsniaga dellup niatpaC eht
”.draobrats og uoy“
.devresed eh naht erom on saw hcihw ,lufepoh dnuos t’ndid eH
,drawrof tniop ot ecaf sih tsap mra ,niaga nehS dniheb saw eh neht yb dnA
”?nam a ni segnahc lufrewop skrow revir eht eerga uoy t’ndluow tuB
,gnirps yrd a dah yeht syas pissog tub ,nippots tuohtiw anaisiuoL ot yaw eht lla taolf tsuj ,dloh lluf a ekil d’I“
.denethgirf ylnialp dna ,delggardeb ,tew
”nihton ro dnuorga su nur t’noD“
.gnirevihs saw eh dna ,srae sih revo demmaj saw pac htolc a ,dekaos erew sehtolc siH
,flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
”,niatpaC ,recnamelet a htiw ni kcehc ll’uoY“
”?no peels ot uoy ekil gul gib a tog yeht ,deb rehtaef a sdeen ohW
.syad eerht ni netae t’ndah tuo dnif dluoc I tseb
,kcab rentrap sih dloh ot fi sa mra s’dnuohdoolb eht ot dnah a pu tup gnilrats pmulp eht ”,ereht woN“
.niktiA pota yal nehS  ).gnos s’revir eht gnis ll’uoy dna kcommah sih ni mih nioj oS(
”?erofeb taob a dereets reve uoY“.seye
”!nrob saw eh yad eht sa edun si“
”,n’paC“ .omluztiF dias
,morf rey erehw …ees s’tel oS
”?ap rey tuoba tahW .hO“ ”.suirebiT
.knab tfel eht drawot ,yltneg
.flesmih rohtua eht rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
,ti eveirter ot retaw eht otni deppils
’kcommah a erahs‘ ot reffo eht nrael ot esirprus a neeb ti t’ndah dna—
klof elbatcepser yltnerappA
gnirevoh tsuj erew sdnah s’niatpac eht dna flesmih rellit eht dleh nehS llit
”.nideef tuoba ees ot htuom artxe na yltnerappa dna ,od ot krow tog su fo emos tub“ ,deppop redluohs sih llit sgniw sih dehcterts
.tey depacse t’nia eh os ,liart sih no llits m’I“
.ecalp rieht ni wal eht ot revo nik esoht nrut neht ,tuoba nik rieht llet t’nod yeht stbed terces pu nur OD klof elbatcepser yltnerappa
,epip bocnroc gnillems-luof a til ylraE
.sdoom rieht gnihgiew ,sffirehs eht deye retto eht ”,lleW“
”!etam ,eman rey thguac I kniht t’noD“