yppah eb nac gniteem siht erE
tol tnacav eht tsap tsuj tfel A
,gninrom emosraef eht emac oS
.gniyats ton erew snoitareneg regnuoy eht woh fo deklat dnA
,teiuq dna elbatcepser saw snoitnetnI dooG fo nwot ehT
,gnihton era ecnedivorp ot
regnuh suoyoj ni no egrahC knabwons eht nopu tnecs eht tsrif sehctac ohw flow eht seod sA meht dael eh dnA
,gnignis meht ediseb dniw eht
,gnihceeseb yhtapmys ,ohw
.noitisop koot eH .ekawa ekib sih dekcik eH
,dnaltraeh dna emoh sa
.era ew tahw ediced sevlesruo tub ydobon tel ohw ,sretfihsepahs gnieb roF
hsiugnal taht snwot ynam sa teiuq dna elbatcepser sA
redael delzzirg rieht litnU
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gnillet ot emac eh selat dnA
.snoiton rieht sepacse ’woh‘ hguoht
,snoitnetnI dooG fo nwot eht no
.rehtohcae ni htgnerts dnif ohw stsactuo gnieb roF
.gninruter tuohtiw os did
.snoitcennoc lagidorp ot dna noitaler ot dedneterP
floWcaM boR yb meop a
snoitnetnI dooG morf sdaor taht
,snoitnetnI dooG ni ,devil ehs elihw ,emoclew eb tey dluow eh tahT
yawhgih dna ecnedivorp taht yad eht eb thgim yad yna roF
,namuh a ekil depahs deb ehT
.tnemom a rof ylno tuB
,ytnuoC auqcahenniM ni
htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rorret a saw tsomerof ehT
rehto eht ot ,detaeper
”llewsrehsU leinaD fo gnimocemoH ehT“ saw sihT
,kniht I ,wonk I ,yaw siht saw tI“
.meht tegeb-er dna nrut ot
.morf denruter eno taht erehwyna ot ton deL
.sdnalssarg ytsud sseldne eht ni
senigne rieht devver mih ediseb sevlow ehT ”.kcab emoc seod reven dnA
,suoiruc-tsiruot ,no dekool uoy fi
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT no
.raef naht erom ni sreh ekil ecaf oT
.srettel fo sesimorp htiw
,snoitnetnI dooG fo nwot eht morF
,ti dniheb erew neppah thgim sgniht nehw syad eht taht gnigduj roF
,neerg dna der gnignahc desaeC
,sevlowerew tsniag dias saw drow a fi dnA .llew sa kcap sih lla dnA
.derettuhs ecnis gnol won ,erots taht morf ydnac emos elots I ecno tahT
,spets hcrop nrow eht detnuom eH
no yrteop sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.reverof ton hguoht ,yawa tfiws esirnus eht rednu deraor yehT
ecalp siht demialc ecno flow tnatsid emos fi sA
,esiwrehto ro doog ,snoitnetni tuB
.sretsnom thguoht gnieb roF
ereht tsuj ,traeh ta kcis ,detiaw I ecno tahT
.mih dloh eh did ylthgit
,secnarussa ekam tsum hcae yehT
,hsiflow dna dekciw tlep eht fO
.sdnalssarg gnillor ,dekramer erom on tub ,elbakramer ecno eht nI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,daeh yggahs sti koohs dnA
.rebmemer eh seod llits tey
,eert mle taht htaeneb
,floWcaM boR yb meop a uoy gnidaer m’I yadoT dna
ti morf tuo del ecno taht sdaor ehT
,tsegnuoy rieht dnuor deldduh yehT
,mih nihtiw erob eh flow eht htiw derutximda god fo hcuot A
snoitnetnI dooG fo nwot ylenol eht sevael taht sub eht hctac oT
sserac hguor a htiw dnA
.neppah thgim gnihtyna taht yad eht eb yam yad yna dnA
thgilpots ylno dna enol ehT
,hcae ot emoc ot dah flow eht woh fO
ecnedivorp ro etaf ro ecnahc oT
,mih dnuora kcap regae sih htiw ,selbboc fo erauqs eht otnO
eeffoc rof tem
.egap yrruFoS sih no
,gnillet eht niaga ecno degaruocne
.dlohserht eht dnoyeb raef ni ereht doots dlo eb ton ot dlo ooT namow A
,tnemevaereb dna noom eulb fo
llebrood railimaf gnol-sedaced a ,niaga draeh dna ,desserp eH
retaw gniwolf ekil dniw eht htiW
.su ekil enoemos ees ot detcepxe reven taht morf emoc ew secalp eht lla morf gnimoc roF
.rehtom sih htiw tisiv ot ,kcap sih lla htiw ,kcab mih gnirb dluoC
uoy llet nac ,owt ro flow a htiw pihsnik emos mialc ohw ,I tuB
,ecnelis ot meht demlac lworg a htiw
.ti dias ohw esoht ot evig ot dnim fo eceip a evah dluow ehs ,yhW
.neddibrof lla erew selcihev rotom erehW
:gnixaw saw noom eht tey elihw
.dedracsid sgniht namuh lla htiw
,denodnaba sksam dna ,nrecnoc lla
.spotllih gnillor eht neewteb dih
,enuJ ni yad detnuah tnorf-dloc enO
senigne rieht ni rednuht a htiw ,yawhgih eht nwod emac kcaP eht hO
ti detraped ohw ynam dnA
,nettogrof llef ti nehw sA
,”llewsrehsU leinaD fo gnimocemoH ehT“   yojne esaelP
.mih dniheb kcap gniyab eht htiw
,snoitnetnI dooG tisiv ot ,won ,nosaer dah deedni wef roF
,sdnalhtron eht fo tserof eht ni
,enigne na ni rednuht ehT
,denekawa saw regna rieht tub fi ,od ylerus dluoc kcaP eht tahW
.noisulli sti dna maerd sti saw namuh eht elihW
,sosrot erab dna smra erab revo
,tserof eht ni eb dluow I dna
.ti llac uoy revetahw ro
,klofsnwot eht no saw raef a tahW
sselraef dna eerf gninnur-A
,yromaylop dna edirp fO
,meht nopu kcaP eht thguorb tahT
,yawhgih eht nwod meht del eH
derebmuls dah ti yletal erehw
romur mohw ,erom gnihton dna ,gnag rekib a erew yeht yas emoS
.denrut eh neht dnA
,teews erom saw noinuer hguone noos dnA
.deraef gnieb roF
,ytnuoC auqcahenniM lla ni
,mih nihtiw erow eh tlep eht fo roloc yrev eht daer dluoc enO selpmet sih evoba enam eht ni dna
.detniap dah flesmih ecno eh taht ,xobliam detsur eht dessap eH
)ynam ton erew ereht( nwot eht fo sredle ehT gninrom eht nI
.yletamitlu ,rohpatem a s’tI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.retnuoc eht nopu derrup rekam eeffoc eht dna ,reppuS hciwdnas dalas nekcihc a rof ,nekorb saw daerbrednoW dnA
.erehwemos neppah ot sah ti ,llew ,sneppah yllanif ti nehw dnA
regnuh rieht ro regna rieht fI
,gnineve emos ,raeh thgim uoy erehT
,gninrom eht ni reh tfel yehT
.wolley gnihsalf ylno dewohs daetsni
.yleritne esle gnihtemos roF .rohpatem ylerem meht kniht emoS
,selcsum sti dehcterts ,denekawa ecno
.kcab werd rood eht no tlobdaed eht erofeb semit eerhT
mih dellac ehS .depsag ehS
mih dlot ehS .dootsrednu ehs dias ehs
,ylthgit mih thguac redael delzzirg ehT
.gnillet eht ni elat llat ciporhtnacyl ot sah detalfnI
detfihs reh erofeb flow eht roF
,renid a eb ot desu erehw
.seilferif eht dehctaw eh ecno erehw
teiuq sa ton si ,syadawon ,snoitnetnI dooG fo nwot eht tahT
.gnitiaw yawevird levarg eht ni meht tfel eH
,mih dessik yeht epahs nevlow ni yltnaifed dna ylnialp hcaE
,yltfiws su llet dna ,pup su lleT ?gniog er’ew ti si erehw oS“ ,ereht delwoh eh dnA
.edisdaor eht sa delzzirg dna yerg
,emac noissecorp mirg ni kcaP ehT
,em syamsid nwot namuh siht roF
.rebmemer I taht kniht I
tes saw nus eht ere oS
,esuohtruoc eht erofeb erauqs eht ot
,derebmuls dah ti erehw deb eht fo tuo pael nevlow a tpael dnA ,seninac dekciw gniyalpsid denway dna
hpmuirt lairotirret ni teewsrettib tey ,lwoh ffo-raf dnA
),noitatuper yb( wenk yeht rof
,rettib ssel hcum dna
,noitagergnoC tsriF tsidohteM eht erofeb tfel rehtonA
”.ereht eb nac ew renoos eht“
.meht evig ll’ew ycavirp emoS  ”?leinaD“
thgilpots ylno eht htaenrednu
,ycaripsnoc erew yeht kniht emoS
,dias eh ”,enod era ew renoos ehT
,mih evol ot dnuof d’eh kcap eht fo
keehc sih no elbbuts eht nI
,retnec nwot ta sdaorssorc eht no ,thgilpots enol eht tesnus tA
,reffid snoinipo ,esruoc fo woN
.sniatruc eht neewteb reep dna sdnilb eht tuhs dna srood eht tuhs diD ,klofsnwot eht suhT
,ti dekool eh hguoht ,regnuoy hcum ton ,mih ediseb eno dias ”,kniht I“
,deretne eh hguone noos tuB
,nevigrof eb dluoc uoy dnA
,gnicar meht ediseb dniw eht dna senigne rieht ni rednuht eht htiW
,rehtael dedaf ni no emac eH
,tnelis nellus dna llits yal
.retsnom a ton era tey yeht ,secnaraeppa lla etipsed tahT
,nekops eb tsum worros hcuM
.syawhgih derdnuh ynam woh htiw delzzirg dna deyerg rehtael nI
,stimil ytic eht edistuo tsuj
,noitailicnocer hcum dna
,laibrevorp deedni saw tI
,yawhgih eht nwod gnirednuht sA
,esuoh hcnar elbmuh a erofeB
,erom on ereh htellewd eh hguoht dnA
yawhgih ytsud yna nwod ,niaga yaw ruoy tnew uoy erofeB
.srotom rieht deppots dna sekib rieht dellats yehT .tlah a ot emac kcaP ehT
.sdnalssarg eht ssorca mrots a ekil
,sevitiguf erew yeht taht yas emoS
rehtohcae edam d’yeht emoh fO
.senigne rieht evoba draeh eb ot ton staorht rieht ni gnilworg a htiW
,srehtorb sih lla democlew ehs dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,flesmih gnicudortni ekil gnihtemos od ot tuoba t’nsi ohw
”!sdleifnroc eht ta sdaorssorc eht ot teg uoy nehw thgir a neht dnA
.lla ti fo etips ni emoh yaw ruo gnidnif rof dnA
.ssenisub elbaknihtnu no
,gnixaw saw noom eht tey elihw ,enuJ ni yad gninetaerht tnorf-dloc enO
noinuer ni meht nopu detisiv saw saw ti ohw nO
,sdnalssarg eht ssorca gniohce
.yrarbil eht yb ,dnuorgyalp taht ni ereht seenk ym denniks I ecno tahT“