,reh erongi ot drah dekrow eH
selcarim esuaceB
dnif dluoc eh stfig eht lla erew
.daeh sih ni snoitseuq eht tuo gnihsup
.meht rednu thguac esoht fo senob eht llihc ot nwod gniniar sekalfwons eht no wolg yna ees t'ndid dna
,emit tsrif eht rof dnA
.ssenizal gniyaper saw ehs
.eh saw ron ,niaga neht tuB
.yaD s'enitnelaV taht no
traeh eht morf dehcterts eb dluoc taht secarg niht eht rof
ynnub etihw gnilbmert eht eciton t'ndid tsomla eh
.yad taht no cigam nees evah dluoc toidi na ylnO
,egawes raen gnivil
srewes eht ni mih nioj ot ynnub eht dlot eh
.noonretfa samtsirhC taht no lluf snac egabrag eht dna
,aksarbeN ,ahamO fo tuo tneduts wal tnerruc dna
.taht ni elcarim oN
.edistuo ton tsael ta
,rewolf dettor taht
.yawyna hserf erew yeht fi derettam evah t'ndluow ti
.og ot ecalp yna evah t'nod I"
.redluohs sih no pihc a htiw taots hsilgnE dehtuom-luof a deyalp ecno noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy erehw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,stfig eht ta kool ot sdnah sih kcab dellup eh sa pu deretaw seye siH
.flesmih ot thguoht eh
.yrots reh fo ytleurc eht yb nekorb traeh sih dnuof tar ehT
,spmal lacimehc eht rednu roolf ykcits eht gnola deklaw yeht sA
,kcab derats ehs nehw tuB
si yrots s’yadot dna
ytuaeb citsemod taht gnillup
.sretspmud fo spot eht morf swodniw hguorht gnikool
,xoftiK ozirraC yb ”tfiG s’taR ehT“
,dnopser ot kciuq erew stnerap evitcetorp revo riehT
,hguoht ,hguor oot reh htiw deyalp dah yehT
,roolf dehsaw eht no teef sih tup eh emit yrevE
hcum os mih deregna ti yhw s'tahT
.thguac saw eh gnizilaer
.htuom reh ot swap reh stup ehS
.gnidliub a fo toof eht ta delruc
.srehto fo etsaw eht
.mih rof gnitiaw eno ehT
.rewol saw traeh sih hguoht ,nwod srae sih
,deppans eh "!emoh og
.eno tib dna deracs tog ehs dna
tar rewes ytrid a fo
yltfos gnikcarc eciov reh ,deksa ehs
gnihton dias ehs
.egabrag eht fo tser eht htiw tuo reh gniworht
.rof gnitiaw htrow t'nerew ylniatrec yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.flesmih derebmemer eh
.lacigam tib elttil a neeb dah samtsirhC taht
.ekops ehs yllaniF
lennut gnihsulf desunu eht ni yats ynnub eht tel ot tar eht del taht kaerbtraeh taht saw ti ebyaM
.tihs esroh taht ni seveileb eno on tuB
.mih yaper ot dluoc ehs gnihtyna gniod no detsisni ehs woh
gnihtyna gnitpecca rof mih gnuts tI
sdnah ysaerg sih nI
.yad yreve sparcs gnitae
,gniknis traeh sih ,deppots eH
mih deknaht ehs woh saw ti ylekil erom tuB
.tiaw reh edam evah reven dluow eh
,gnidloh saw eh tahw deksa ehs nehW
,egabrag eht reh dewohs eH
.dnuof eh ynnub taht ekiL
,rof tiaw ot gnihton si sihT
tar rewes a rof emit tcefrep a saw tI
,llems eht tuoba denialpmoc reven ehs woh
,loopssec sih otni
.seihtapmys tneinevnocni tuo nward dah yresim reh woh ta deyonna
saw sihT   ————   .neppah nac
.gnuts mih fo trap a ,tae ot doof dna
.noitautis reh denialpxe ehs
,reh ot delrans eh
.edis tsae eht deraelc eh nehw ereht llits saw ehs dnA
.yaw taht reisae saw tI
emoh mraw a reh gnivig rof
ereht llits saw ehS .eh did ron os
.hguoht ,diputs saw tI
.wenk eh lla saw tI
.erom nezod a neht
,won did eh tahw nwonk dah eh fi tuB
ot ton sesucxe nezod a htiw pu emac eH .erows eH
,efil sih lla srewes eht ni devil dah eH
.gninrom taht eert eht rednu reh dnuof yldeticxe ohw
.samtsirhC no neppah selcarim yas yehT   xoftiK ozirraC yb
,ytic eht ni gnoleb t'ndid stibbaR
repoleved emag remrof a
.rewes sih ni emoh kcab gnitiaw eno ehT
,nib hsart a fo mottob eht ta xob a morf deparcs erew setalocohc ehT
noonretfa samtsirhC nezorf taht kool doog a dah tar ehT
.teerts eht fo edis tsew eht deraelc eh nehw
.ecnelis reh yb deregna
ebyam taht tlef tar eht
,xoftiK ozirraC yb "tfiG s'taR ehT"
,devresed ehs tahw morf kcab reh gnidloh saw gniod saw eh llA
thgir nwo sti ni tsacdop a dna
,ssendnik gniyaper t'nsaw ehS
.ysae eb ot desoppus erew sgnihT
"tfiG s'taR ehT":yojne esaelP
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.skeew ot denrut yats reh nehw
,dloc gnitteg saw tI
niaga mih knaht reh ot denetsil eh emit yreve
.efil sih ni nees reve dah eh naht
,ssendnik sih rof ylsseldne
.oreh a ekil mih ta dekool ehs nehw
rewolf taht yhw si hcihW
.esufer t'ndluoc eh
,pac elttob taht gnihctulc sdnah ysaerg sih ta dekool eh sA .saw eh lla
.rewes sih fo htmraw eht ot kcab og ot detnaw eh dna
.lennut eht otni deppets ehs nehw niard a nwod lla ti worht ot tuoba saw eH
.cigam fo tnih a toN
wenk ylno eh sgniht eht lla
"?em rof esoht tog uoY" .delims ehS
.yad rehto yna sa seitleurc emas ehT
mih ta kcab dekool ehs sa seye reh dehctaw eH .srae sih detfil tar ehT
,kcab dekool tsuj ehS ".edisni teG"
.rettug eht ta flesmih deppots eh nehw esnes yna ekam t'ndid ti yhw si hcihW
.lennut gniohce eht nwod
.meht ni htlif nwo sih lla gniees
.etatiseh t'ndid ehS   .pu mraw ot
,dias I" .gnihton gniyas
,noitaicossA llabteksaB yrruF eht gnidnuof rof nwonk tseb
.tnemom yreve htroW .saw ehs tuB
,gnizeerf ,gnikahs
,egabrag yb gnivil ,enola gnivil
.hsart yhtlif ,ysaerg saw eH
.samtsirhC saw ti dnA
.gnitliw dna dettor saw dnah sih ni rewolf ehT
.emahs reh yb erom neve dellihc dekool ehS ".og
.erusaert laer eht saw ehs ,ruf etihw gnimaelg reh htiW
seihtapmys niht esoht ebyam dnA .emoh dellac eh
.stfig t'nerew esehT
,esuoh naelc ,mraw a ni eb ot ecnahc a dah ehS
— ytinummoc yrruf eht rof tcejorp strops ysatnaf gninnur-gnol-edaced a
,rof derac dna demoorg ,doof doog def
,meht fo eno yreve etipsed dnA
gnihtyna gniyas morf mih tpek tahw erew
,seirrebnarc fo nac tuo nworht a fo edisni eht gnikcil fo thguoht eht ta gniretaw htuom sih htiW
.teerts eht ruocs ot
s'taht esuaceB   .mih ekil
.reeb fo dekeer taht pac elttob a ni derehtag
",ereh tuo ezeerf gnikcuf ot gniog er'uoY .gnimoc s'thgiN"
goD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sregnif reh no delbbin ehS
nerdlihc emos rof tfig samtsirhC a sa thguob neeb dah ehS
ytpme erew sdaor ehT
setalocohc esoht dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
eurt erom yoj a htiw
.denworf eH .derats tar ehT