ecitsuj eht mih od ot detnaw ecnaL
efil rieht rof noitaicerppa retaerg a uoy sevig osla ti tub
mih ot erusolc evig ot pleh dluow ti thguoht ylno ecnaL tub
.ti rof hguone dlo saw ylniatrec koob ehT
.yltaen yrev dereyal saw gab lluf ylraen eht ,deednI
.nuf gnivah eb ot demees sretirw htob
,sdiulf ylidob yna fo sniats on
.enimre daed a dna ,renilcer dlo na
luferac erom neve saw ecnaL
.stseug ynam yrev dah tsuguA taht noisulcnoc eht ot emoc ot ecnaL desirprus rehtar evah dluow ti ,tnemtrapa eht fo etats eht htiw ,hguohT
.woh wenk uoy yaw ylno eht
.flesmih ot daer ot
,leep egnaro na pota
htaeD dna efiL ehT“
,erom ecno lufesu devorp
,dnah ta esac eht eb ot rettal eht detcepsus reyD ecnaL
–boj doog yrev a gniod t’nerew yeht
,skcals dna trihs deralloc a erow tsuguA
,cisum htiw dellif saw nehctik eht ,ylnedduS
,raef dna ,elib dna
,mih woleb hsulp eht otni ylivaeh knus enimre eht
gnissim saw tahw yb enecs a enifed ot lufpleh sa tsuj saw ti thguoht eh sa
,ydob eht brutsid ot ton tnaem osla saw eH
,syaw emos ni ,dna
,hcum sa detcepsus dah ecnaL
.dehcuotnu ylraen dekool koob yreve dna hcaE
.ni dekcut eb ot dednetni erew ti hguoht sa
,knis eht dellif sehsiD
,thguoht ecnaL ,neeb dah yeht fi ,hguohT
.ni yoj dnif ot meht rof gnihtemos emaceb
srepap fo selip hgih yllacitsilaernu derewot renroc eno nI
,hguoht ,ecnaL ot tseretni fo saw nehctik eht ni esle elttil yreV
repap fo eceip dedlof llams a dnuof ecnaL nehw
.renroc llams eno otni sevlesmeht enifnoc ot gniganam llits hguoht
nuF‘ fo eman eht yb
ssenthgirb eht deyojne ecnaL tub
,rewop rehgih yna ni eveileb yllacificeps ton did ecnaL elihw ,dnA
.morf gnihtyna naelg ot mih rof kcolc a neve ro
,resserd eht pota tuo dial ylgnivol tsomla
,tniop emos ta neeb ylraelc dah ro ,derae-god erew segap sti fo ynaM
,saw taht efil a del ohw enoemos fo erutcip eht rehtag mih pleh dluoc ti
,won rof lleweraf narocroC tsuguA dib ot
,narocroC tsuguA fo wenk eh tahw gniwonK
,teY .yad yrev taht
.nehctik eht ot yaw sih dnuof reyD ecnaL
.denottub erew htob taht nevig neve
’.adnegA lauxesomoH
,ereht neeb reve dah eno ngis on dna
.no ydaerla saw elbat edis eht no pmal A
,dna ,ytiruces fo tros yna htiw mih ot tnemrag eht dloh ot hguone etiuq t’nsaw ti hguoht sa demees
,hserf ytnelp dekool taht
noitnetta sih denrut dna
.esoprup cificeps yrev a dah hcae dna
revocsid ot kciuq saw ecnaL tub
.ot yvirp ton saw eh
,)saw eh ,thguoht eh ,hcihw( ,skoob naht elpoep fo sega gnitamitse ta retteb yna saw ecnaL fi ,enimre ehT
.evol tsom eht was egap revetahw ot thgir
.setadpu erom rof rettiwT no meht wollof ro
.seton wef yreve hctiws dluow selyts eht
,deciton ecnaL ,yllaniF
.os gniod fo noitnetni yreve dah eh dna
,egap elgnis yreve fo snigram eht hguorht gnidaer ylluferac tuohtiw dluoc eh lla denrael dah eh taht gnidiced
,gnithgilhgih eht htiw denrecnoc erom raf saw eH
.dehsilbup saw ti nehw seitnewt dim dna sneet etal sih neewteb erehwemos neeb evah dluow
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,dnatsrednu ot boj s’ecnaL saw ti ,teY
.goD fo ecioV ehT no tubed rieht gnikam si ohw ,aneY irA yb
,niaga ta kool reven dna edisa ssot thgim eno sgniht fo stros lla dna sepolevne dna srettel dna
dnuof eH .gnihton dnuof tub ,hcuoc eht detcepsni eH
.taht saw taht dna
,yltneg esolc ot koob eht dewolla ecnaL
.rood eht morf nees eb dluoc ,tnemtrapa llams eht ni sgniht rehto tsom ekil hcum
.detpurretninu eb ot krow sih rof dna ,suolucitem eb ot dekil tsuj eH
,shgiht s’tsuguA fo spot eht naht rehgih ylraen saw gnirevoc cirbaf nat sti fo pot yrev eht taht os hcum os
,nam gnuoy esiw a gnieb ,reyD ecnaL
enoyna tcatnoc ot niatrec gnikam fo
.tcerroc saw eh taht
mih yartrop ot erus ekam ot dna
.tneps emit sih ni derehtag eh tahw tuoba denialpmoc ecno reven dah uaessuoR
.detaroireted ylwols yeht sa dne no skeew rof stnemtrapa rieht ni pu sevlesmeht deloh ohw elpoep fo stros eht htiw
,ecnalg a ta wonk ot dedeen uoy gnihtyreve uoy llet dluoc ,semit ta
.taen ti peek dna nwod ti wols ot
,flesti retnuoc eht otni tuo llips ot sa raf os gniog neve
.gninaelc dedeen nwo sih taht ecnaL dednimer
tleb sih woleb pu gnihcnub
.taht saw taht dnA
,ytpme raen saw egdirf eht
,koob dnoces eht ot
,yarg erew deb sih fo steehs ehT
.sdrac dna sepolevne lufroloc dna citcelce tsom eht niatnoc ot demees raf yb tsellat ehT
eno tsehtruf taht neve dna
.semit fo sderdnuh
.nihtiw egap eht gnitcetorp neeb d’yeht hguoht sa
nwot eht tuoba erom denrael ecnaL
.yad sih ot gnirb thgim ti
,segap eht ni deniatnoc cirotehr eht fo ytisnetni eht etipseD
,deid dah narocroC tsuguA taht
.stseug yna gniteerg saw ti hguoht sa tsomla
narocroC tsuguA hguoht sa
,slaem nezorf evres elgnis ylno fo lluf rezeerf eht dna
troffe detrecnoc a gnikam erew yeht taht
.elip eht fo mottob eht no esoht yltsom erew esoht hguoht
.ylluf enimre eht gninifed ni
eeZ‘ dna ’,puorG lacideM
,kcab uaessuoR txet ot rehtob t’ndid ecnaL ,semit tA
,noitamitse s’ecnaL yb ,sraey 03 tsael tA
segap owt neewteb ,retnec eht dnuora thgir
noitaerc nwo s’enimre eht
.ffuc eht dnuora tnenimorp yllaicepse saw gniyarf taht hguoht
,rennid VT dedracsid a pota
niaga dedlof dna
,emit yna ta rewsna sih dnif dluoc eh elihw ,dna
retirw dnoces ehT
hsart s’enoemos hguorht kool a tub
,gnissap sih fo wonk ot tnaw dluow eh ohw
,flesmih ecnaL neve erofeb
,s’ecnaL fo etirovaf a(
,lla ta thgis ni noisivelet on htiw tnemtrapa na dnif ot egnarts saw ti thguoht ecnaL
,thgim ti erehw nepo llaf ot koob eht dewolla ecnaL
—lla ta seton etiuq t’nerew seton esoht tuB
esuap mih evag taht
emit eht ta ekil saw dlrow eht tahw fo egdelwonk siH
.slerriuqs tuoba dias yeht tahw wenk eh tub
,fo kniht dluoc eh lla ,tcaf ni ,saw tI
.lla fo suoiruc tsom eht eno siht
,deltit saw egap eht nehw
.llaw eno gnola tas ,gniroloc rethgirb sti ni ecalp fo tuo yrev dna
deltit ,fo draeh reven dah ecnaL koob a fo ypoc revocdrah a ,tsrif ehT
’.ecnarusnI ytilibasiD rof retneC lanoitaN‘
.dereffus neeb sah taht ssol taerg eht rof dna
selppa dna sehcaep dna segnaro htiw hgih dekcats
.tsud fo reyal kciht sti ni ssenilenol fo snosaes ynam gniees ,regnol raf rof
.denekawa ti nehw no emoc evah thgim lennahc tahw ees ot
.saw ylurt eh nam eht sa yletarucca
.edisni deppets eh tnemom eht delfits tlef eH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
resserd eht no talf tuo ti gniyal
,stnap sih fo tsiaw pu dehcnub eht yb gnigduj
,daeh sih fo pid rehtona htiW
,was eh tahw sa hcum sa tsuj
,sgniht s’narocroC tsuguA hguorht elfir ot gniog saw eh fI
.gnirettel der dlob ni ’TNEGRU‘
ehT‘ ,gnimialc saw ti demussa dah ecnaL tahw sa dlob sa
,moor bard eht gniretne nopu was eh ,dna
,sraet thgils ro sdlof ro srae-god fo naelc yleritne erew taht
renkluaF‘ ’,egagtroM ylimaF
,etad gnihsilbup eht saw 4891 —erom eb dluoc ti kniht ot thgir saw eh mih dlot revoc eht edisni ecnalg a
,rennid VT dedracsid A
.sdnekoob tsilaminim rehtar owt neewteb pu denil yltaen
.narocroC tsuguA ton tub
ot denepo eb ot detnaw koob a erehw gnitset fo ygetarts siH ’.emoH
,segassap eht ni deniatnoc sdrow eht gnitufer erew yeht rehtehW
.pu gnilip selttob reeb ro sttub etteragic on
.erom elttil yrev dna ,klaw ot ecaps hguone tsuj saw erehT
,deb eht no selip elttil nwo rieht ni lareves erew ereht hcihw fo
,depmuls saw narocroC tsuguA hcihw no riahc ehT .llew yrev
,emoh a fo hcraes sih etelpmoc ot ecnaL koot ti emit eht tuoba stnialpmoc eht lla rof ,dnA
,eb dluoc ssob sih tneitapmi woh ecnaL derehtob syawla dah tI
neeb evah tsum tahw fo seloh lanoitidda wef A .devol llew
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,emit sih fo hcum os tneps eh hcihw ni nevah lanosrep sih edavni ot
,lufknaht saw ecnaL hcihw fo
.enimre eht ot ti dewo eH
”narocroC tsuguA fo
’.seviL ruO ot taerhT ehT‘
t’ndid eh taht ylderussa os wonk ot hguoht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
tpircs decitcarp yrev a ni etorw retirw tsrif ehT
,ecnaL ot esnes gnikam t’nsaw narocroC tsuguA tuoba gnihtemos tuB .hguone noos rewsna sih evah d’eh taht gniwonk
meht esrap neve dluoc eh erofeb aedi na ecnaL evag ’mriF gnidneL setaicossA dna
,evol ot demees seitreporp latner wen ro stnemtrapa ro semoh ynam roloc llehsgge emas taht erew sllaw ehT
.narocroC tsuguA tuoba naht
,ti was ecnaL sa ,gnitsartnoc ,wolley fo daerht esool a yb
,hguoht ,rekcins a kcab dloh ot dah eH
moor eht ni esle lla naht rewen hcum gnikool ,hcuoc A
.dootsrednu eb ot tnaem reven erew taht
dnuof dah eh yaw gnimoclewnu dna yssem taht ni ,tuoba nwerts erew sgniht hguoht sa t’nsaw tI
.erew sgnitirwdnah gnireffid yltsav eht
.nep eht gnippord retfa noos oot desolc neeb evah thgim koob eht nehw ro ,edis kcab eht hguorht delb yeht nehw
,erom yna enotgnir a sa tros yna fo cisum desu enoyna taht erar ylniatrec saw tI
.doof hserf ylralucitrap ro
snoitaroced ro seceip tra on erew erehT
.koot rohtua lanigiro eht enot ythguah eht gnikcimim erew yeht spahrep ro
,tsrif taht fo edis eht ot tsuj
.dnuora gniggid suoires yrev emos deriuqer ,semit ta ,dna
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
ffuc eht ot denetsaf saw tfel ehT
,tneb saw renroc a ton dna
ecnatsni ralucitrap siht ni esuaceb
sdrow eht fo hcum fo enot evisnopser eht fI
tsud fo reyal kciht taht fo eerf elbat eht no ecaps ylno eht dna
,tey enots ni gnitirw elbatrofmoc tlef ecnaL taht hcum t’nsaw erehT
,gniteem a dnetta ot elba eb thgim eh erehw dna
.lla retfa ,ecaps sih no gnidurtni saw ecnaL
thgir enod saw ti erus ekam dna setar tseb eht htiw enod boj eht teg dluow ohw
,dessap dah ohw esoht fo seidob eht ees ot reisae ti ekam yam efil ruoy ni htaed hcum os gniees esuaceb
,nevo eht sa emit emas eht ta nepo t’ndluoc egdirf ehT .mih rof tnaem
.dedeen eh gnihtemos saw taht
dedlof neeb dah ti fi sa niht sa gnikool dlof hcae ,trapa emoc ot tuoba demees repap dedlof eht
,drow sih evig ot ,)dessap ecnis(
.tibah fo erutaerc a saw ,demees ti ,narocroC tsuguA
etihw gnirob emas eht rettel elgnis yreve ,mrofinu yltcefrep saw tI
eno rellams hcum a
,rehtegot tup ,syaw emos ni
tih pop eno rebmun eht fo surohc eht
potevots s’enimre eht saw taht ssem eht gniees taht morf trapa
,elbat ytsud a ,hcuoc ylgu na
.yas ot gniyrt saw ti tahw dnatsrednu ot ti rednu txet eht daer ot deen t’ndid ecnaL
,flesmih ot ecnarussa emos htiw sgniht eseht fo hcae deton ecnaL dnA
.yllacitsilyts tsael ta ,erom raf reyD ecnaL detseretni
.eton fo tros ylno eht t’nsaw taht taht
,erew yeht sa sgniht ees ot tluciffid erom ti ekam thgim erac sih spahrep taht
,gnicitne dna wen dnarb
.rebmulp a dedeen eh fi
.draeh evah reven thgim llew yrev
,)nosrep a tuoba erom uoy llet nac elttil yrev sa
,saw ti ,noitatcepxe taht ot ,dnA
.tcaf eht retfa derrucco deneppah taht gnigdums yna taht raelc saw ti dna ,dnah ydaets a htiw dna
1 traP ,aneY irA yb
.noitasrevnoc a erew yeht
morf narocroC tsuguA ot desserdda erew yeht sa
,delaes deniamer eno yreve dna hcaE
,htgnel ni ylralucitrap
.emit tsal eno moor eht revo dekool dna
.saw ti gnirob yllasrevinu woh fo esuaceb ylno fi
,hguoht ,erew eseht srettel fo tros tahw enimreted ylisae dluoc ecnaL
,egap elohw a hguorht deelb semitemos ot hguone
,elip lanif dna driht eht saw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.lla ta denepo neeb d’yeht ezilaer ot sessap wef a
elip dnoces taht neewteb thgir gnittiS
,won erehwemos eb thgim tsuguA taht ytilibissop eht tuo delur yleritne ton dah eh
,enips a ni kcarc a ton saw erehT
,thguoht ecnaL sa ,tnemtrapa eht hcihw fo tros eht
ecnaL ekil lacarac etutsa na neve koot ti taht hguone prahs egde na htiw edalb a htiw ,yltaen dna ylluferac ,denepo saw epolevne hcae ,elddim eht nI
,moordeb ehT .desaeced eht fo
,elbigelli yleritne tsomla txet eht fo snoitrop emos edam
.evila saw eh elihw taerg ylralucitrap dellems evah ton thgim ohw
.taes eht fo segde retuo eht no tsael ta
resserd s’tsuguA fo pot eht ,daetsnI
ekil eht fo gnihtemos ro ssalg dehcte ,lwob a saw
,flesti trihs eht fo eulb peed eht htiw
tuoba tes selip eerht erew ereht ,deednI
detcepsus ecnaL taht yaw a ni ,kcen sih fo kcab eht dnuora pu neve dna
.enimre eht ot tcepser tnelis a ni
.tuo kcuts tsuj eno ,semitemos ,tub ,cisum fo tros taht yojne yllausu t’ndid ecnaL
tsuj spahrep ro ,epahs roop ni saw ,flesti ,tleb tahT
daeh sih deppid ecnaL
,sdnik lla nees dah eh sa
.tnetni erom tib a htiw tuo dekcalb saw ,oot ,txet eht fo emoS
”narocroC tsuguA fo htaeD dna efiL ehT“   yojne esaelP
,deciton ecnaL sa
elbissop thguoht eh naht
htlaeh sih ni tseretni na gniylpmi ton ylniatrec
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,aneY irA yb
.ecivressid a meht gniod eb dluow devol-llew meht llac oT
,noertaP rieht no krow rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY
ecaps eht otni tuo gnittuj erew yeht hguoht sa tlef
.sdrow thgir eht tsuj gnidnif ni ytluciffid emos htiw ti evag eh dna
,sterces rieht tnaw t’ndid
,trapa emoc ot gnitrats erew flesti revoc eht fo segde eht neve dna
,lla ta erehwyna ,retnuoc eht no gniht rehto ylno ehT
,gnol yrev rof sgniht no llewd ot tros eht ton ,ecnaL
,eton eno ni selyts owt eht dnif ot erar saw tI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tsiaw sih dniheb ylno
.]resaet rehto ro regnahffilc eht evloser sretcarahc[ woh tuo dnif ot
,gniht laer eht ton ylniatrec tub latsyrc elbmeser ot edam
,tnes saw txet eht sa krow sih otni kcab thgir evod
,enola nep eht fo erusserp eht yb raelc saw ti srehto elihw ,elyts tsaf dna esool yrev a ni dna
ti gnivil fo yoj eht dna
.deneponu yleritne tas elip eht fo flah pot eht ,nehT
.edisa dehsup ylsuoinomerecnu dna nrut nwo sti nevig neeb dah eno hcae hguoht sa
denottubnu saw ralloc eht hguoht
,yawa skcolb wef a pohs tunod wen eht tuoba denrael eH
”narocroC tsuguA fo htaeD dna efiL ehT“
.tibah emit gnol a saw ti taht delaever
rehto hcae otni nar sdrow rieht fo emoS
.tser eht ekil gnihton erew taht
,tsartnoc krats ni
,deedni ,dnA .erom ebyam
.hguoht ,etal oot lla egnahc a ekam ot gniyrt tsuj t’nsaw eh hguoht sa demees tI
.esle gnihtyna erofeb fo thguoht reyD ecnaL gniht eht saw tahT
,doof fo sparcs on erew erehT
moor eht fo sliated gnimoclewnu esoht saw tI .yhtlaeh
,narocroC tsuguA gnitser eht sdrawot kool ylegas a htiw deddon
.ytpme rehtar saw egral ta moor ehT
,wol saw gniliec ehT
.erofeb shtnom wef a morf
,dertah fo lluf ,sdrow ehT
,tsirw sih dnuora ylthgit ssel hcum gnulc ti
,rehtruf hcum yrev kool ot ton detnaw ecnaL
,erofeb ni senecs ynam os
,gnos pop a saw tI
hcihw fo hcum ,snigram eht ni seton eht ,gninilrednu eht
.drager taht ni wonk ot dedeen eh lla mih llet ot devres
,segassem txet rof eurt yllaicepse saw taht dna
,deveileb eb ot erew dractsop eht no esiarp gnituot eht fi ,denrael eh dna
,nac hsart eht hguorht hcraes A
dessap neeb dah renwo s’ti hguoht sa dekool ti fo tnorf ni elbat A
,neve ,ti decaf tI
.lla dna llems koob wen ,snoitasnes emas yrev eht ecnaL evag eno gninepo dna
,tcepsni ot mih rof noisivelet on saw erehT
.dluoc eh revetahw nrael ot detnaw llits eh
.enod saw gnihctits rehto eht fo lla hcihw yb kcalb eht gnihctam ton ylniatrec dna
emit txen ni enuT
,thgil taht ni nepo yrev dekool moor eht ,dnA
,skoob fo noitcelloc tsedom yrev a htiw denil saw
,leep egnaro na pota
efil siht tuoba sgniht era ereht taht dootsrednu eh esuaceb ,mih gnihctaw
,yub ot ecnaL rof yalpsid no saw eno yreve dna hcae ekil
.niaga emit dna emit spahrep ,gab a otni devohs neeb dah ti hguoht sa
.edisni saw tahw llew yrev wenk eh taht eveileb ot eno dael dluow
sllaw htob denil hcihw stenibac eht dna
.yawklaw eht fo edis etisoppo eht no retnuoc eht gnihcuot tuohtiw lla ta raf yrev nepo yldrah dluoc htob hguoht
,sdaerht eht fo gniyarf thgils eht rof nosaer raelc a evag selknirw ehT
,enecs eht evreserp ot
,thgil mid a tsuJ
,enimre eht fo ecaps lanosrep eht gnidavni rehtruf tuohtiw rehtag dluoc eh lla saw siht sa
,thguoht ecnaL ,efil fo yoj ehT
,sepolevne sti fo ezis dna roloc ni kool mrofinu erom ylthgils a dleh
.lla ta ti ni saw esle elttil yrev esuaceb ,saw tnemtrapa eht fo tser eht sa
,ylesool ylriaf gnuh trihs ehT
,ti otni derutcafunam erew taht esoht tsap dednetxe
,trap tsom eht rof ,dna
,egap eht delrufnu eh sa
moordeb eht ni flesmih dnuof dna
srallod reyapxat sti gnitegduber saw nwot eht taht denrael eh dna
boj taht did eh dna
.etadpu na detnaw uaessuoR
,won rof eciffus ot evah dluow etadpu llams a os
,steknalb eht erew sa ,sesacwollip eht erew sa
—boj eht rof tfos oot saw ecnaL taht dias evah yam emoS
,thgir eht ot derapmoC
,ot ton tluciffid rehtar eb dluow ti dnA
dekcip neeb d’yeht hguoht sa
.demrifnoc tcaf taht evah ot dalg rehtar saw eh dna ,gnihtemos uoy llet syawla lliw
.esac eht ylniatrec saw taht tub
,pot eht ta nepo nrot neve erew emos dna
,hguoht ,sdnekoob eht fo edistuo tas skoob owT
.desaeced eht fo seno devol eht dna
.flesmih enimre eht tuoba gnitseretni esle gnihton dna ,elbat eht rednu gnihton
.mottob yrev eht otni no dna
hguone thgirb tsuj ylno
.ezis dradnats emas eht dna
.moor eht otni ecnaL dewolla taht eno eht morf trapa dnik yna fo sgninepo on ,swodniw on erew ereht taht pleh t’ndid tI
lliH‘ .mottob eht ta esoht fo lla nepo ot elba neeb t’ndah eh fi neve
,hcum sa etacidni ot hguone t’nerew
,daed ylbakatsimnu saw narocroC tsuguA  2 fo
,elip tseggib dnoces ehT