.llaw eht no nettirw s'tahw s'tahT
,4202 ,ht7 yaM dehsilbup eb lliw
dna gninoorc oidar der kcirb eht ot
erehwemos gnitteg eb dluohs uoy ,llaw eht no
.yks eulb gib eht dloh nac srorrim rieht ylno dna
yojne esaelP  .ykseulb
.raey siht retal detcepxe
.yxalag eht fo secils
.doolb ruoy ni nettirw s'tI
.senob sih kaerb ot uoy rof syarp ehs dna
,suproc suebah deussi gnieb tuohtiw nrob er'uoy
eerf er'uoy kniht uoy ,erom yna uoy dloh t'nac srab eht taht gib os worg uoy nehW
”tsaC si thgiL yM erehW fo egdE ehT“
floWcaM boR si sihT
.erehwyreve sllaw era ereht tub
emit drah ni gnittup stsaeb elttil
meop a tneserp ew
,ni nworht t'nera uoY
yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy
sllec fo pu edam si efil ruoY
.uoy llac yeht tahw s'taht esuaceb
,doog eb ot uoy sllet ehs hguoht neve dnA
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
yrots gnimocpu na sa llew sa
,nonniKcM ykS yb
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
nonniKcM ykS yb meop a ,”htnirybaL ehT“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
ni uoy gnillup speek ytivarG
.erutuf eht fo sretirW s’drabbuH noR
.sthgir ruoy daer gnieb tuohtiw
.L fo 2 retrauq ni ecalp dn2 now ohw
.uoy fo   erutcip a tog s'ehS
stnaig leets gnilcric peek uoy tub
.gninrom eht ni deb fo tuo uoy teg ot
.esrup reh edisni ruatonim a fo erutcip a tog s'ehS
no ykS wollof nac uoy ,noitamrofni erom roF
”,daeD gnilwoH eht fo thgiN“ s’lwoH notsruhT ni ”etuC teeM“
.ecarbme gnivol a rof s'ti epoh uoy dna
,rood ruoy no kconk lliw
,nonniKcM ykS yb
.egac a si ytic a fo elddim eht nI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.uoy no dloh a sah tenalp sihT
dnah thgir ruoy htiw klaw dna pu teg uoY
yrots trohs riehT
,skcolb nosirp elttil fo pu edam si ydob ruoy nevE
”htnirybaL ehT“ saw sihT
.sretsnom reh sevol erutan rehtoM
tnemtrapa s'mom ruoy ni birc eht morf
taht wonk uoY .retsnom a er'uoY
nozamA no redroerp rof elbaliava si dna
oreh a swonk ehs