dluoc ,gnivrats saw I erehw doof dnif dluoc flow ehT
”.snoitpo rehto yna naht retteb kcap sih gnikil pu dedne I tuB
.ti deveileb llits I ,taht em thguat ohw elpoep eht morf yawa tog I nehw neve dna
”,htob su dellac deT tahw saw tI“
.duol ylralucitrap ton dna ylenol dna wol
.stoob sih ta pal dluoc retaw eht erehw ot drawrof deppets dna nru eht nekat dah evraH neht dnA
,rehtegot uoy gnignirb roF
.enog saw deT retfa tnereffid kool d’yeht thguoht I tnaem I ,on ,yas ot tuoba neeb d’eH
.ekib s’evraH tsniaga denael eH .derewsna gerG
.thgirb dna kciht srats eht
,degguh yeht dna eiluJ reh dellac nitraM dna
.ecnelis drawkwa otni delttes enoyreve dna ,sdrow rof ria eht ni gnihcraes ,deppots eH
".epahs laer ym ni em sees ohw erac ton ot
,rood eht ta gnidnats saw evraH tub ,ffo syaw a saw tI ”.enod s’evraH“
,tsewhtuos enog d’eh taht llems dluoc naD ,ksam namuh sih ni nevE
.wolloh detserof a ni tol gnikrap elttil a tsuj ekil dekool dah ti ereh morF
,tihs ,daor eht no neeb llits d’yeht fI
.top eeffoc eht trats ot edisni tnew eiluJ nehw ,deksa evraH
.reve sa yvaeh sa dednuop edistuo mrots ehT .emit eb d’erehT
,pu ekorb kcap taht nehw 91 saw I
.eiluJ tem I erehw s’tahT
.emit dnoces a ti tset ot ecnahc a dah yltcaxe t’nevah I“
,yltnatculer ,dnah rieht koohs eH
ot desoppus er’yeht yaw eht ot kcab og nac sgniht dna htiw revo eb ll’ot pu er’yeht esnesnon yag elohw siht dna
.letom eht morf yawa edor yeht nehw dekaos neeb llits dah ti dnuora dlrow eht dna daor ehT
,dedda seliM ”,ylsuoireS“
”.ereh ,rehtie fo secnahc eht rof hcum erac t’nod I tub
.rorrim moortser eht ni flesmih ta derats naD
dalg saw eh yhw si hcihw
,nees reve dah naD llirg pu taeb tsom eht dna elbat cincip a dnuora gnidnats erew yeht won oS
,esiorbuD ettenaeJ saw rehtomdnarg taerg …hu“
.saw I ohw deksa eh tuB
,thgin lla rehtohcae tsniaga dial dna tas yehT
.dehsalf gninthgiL
,detpurretni naD ”,evraH“
.rethgit tog ecarbme ehT ”!dooG“
,hcamots dna tsehc sih no gnitser skeehc dna snihc
”.taht eveileb I fi erus ton m’I“
".rehtie ,od ew tahw yltcaxe yllaer s'taht fo enon" ,naD dias ",lleW"
.detacilpmoc elttil a naht erom yaw saw tahT“ ".tniop
”.erofeb yrots taht draeh reven I“
”.pup ,sknahT .lliw I“
.tey tsuj ,gab gnipeels eht rof rehto hcae morf detaeh oot ,ezeerb thgindim llihc eht ni dekan ,deksa dah eh
ni tsol teg ot sdlrow ediw ylbissopmi gniylpmi sdaorssorC
.mih s’ti ,enola peels t’ndluohs ohw ydobyna s’ereht fI“
.ecnetnes tsal taht gniliared yletarebiled ,dehpmurrah evraH ”.neppah t’ndid
!em ot ti denialpxe reven yeht ,onnud I“
,on ,ylmrif mih dlot gerG dna ,doof teg ot ecalp emos dnif og ot yrt d’eh taht dehgis dah evraH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”?puP“ ,dias seliM ”,tahW“
.yrref eht fo ssergorp eht yb deruoved gnieb retaw eht no dexif seye sih tpek ohw
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,etib emas eht ffo htob thguac I
.newO htiw gnirahs pu dnuow naD
.aes dna hcaeb ykcor fo sehcterts yb nekorb tserof fo sknuhc fo edoc esrom a
.god lautca na yb tib tog tsuj I
.taht demialc enoemos rO
,yawa denrut dna seye sih tuhs eH ”.em sih s’tahT
.deirrow dna ,deretlews dna
,teews oot saw ti ,hcum oot saw ti dog dna ,ruf sih hguorht gnidils tsud yah eht ta koohs ,secnef detluav ,eiriarp eht revo depol eH
,yawtrap ,nepo dils ylwols
s’ti ekil leef tsuj I .sseug I ,rewsna na evah yllaer t’nod I .noitseuq riaF“
.evil ot tnaw I efil a tog ev’I
.revetahW .flow dooG
,niaga ees reven d’eh sdneirf ot eybdoog gniyas elihw
,gniltsirb ruf dna srae
.swap sih otno pu flesmih dehsup naD
,mih dnuora erutsap yssarg eht morf elbahsiugnitsidni ,dnal fo esir llams a no tas eH ".ekil
”.kniht I tahw uoy llet ll’I dna“
.rehtegot emac syellav owt erehw ,daor eht yb dessorc ,dnal fo elddas egnarts a ssorca neeb dah
,toob sih htiw dnatskcik eht pu deparcs dna deggurhs eH
.eman taht mih gnillac fo kniht ot gniyrt driew smees ti tub“ ,dias naD
,llems eht yb llet nac uoy ,dereens dah nitraM ,laicifitra—
.raor niar eht rednu sdrow eht fo yna tuo ekam t’ndluoc naD tub gnivom saw htuom ’seliM
,seliM ot dias naD
”?redlo m’I“ .dias seliM
.kniht uoy tahw ekil ton s'tI"
.noisiv larehpirep s’naD ni evaw gnidnats lanrete na trid dednuom fo swor eht nwod evitcepsrep eht ,yb gnihsalf sdleifnroc
,hgU“ ”.od uoy llit moorhtab yknits siht ni renosirp uoy nipeek m’I
.sevles laer rieht sa meht devresed deT tub
,dias yllanif dah eteP ,lleW
”.kcab em nekat evah t’ndluow yeht ,on hO“
.deT dna evraH .yawynA“
.eromyna ssenisub sti ro kcap s’deT fo trap ton m’I dna
retnuoc eht ot seciohc nwo sih koot eh os ,nialpxe t’ndluoc eh yaw a ni nrolrof tlef naD
,delwoh dna daeh sih kcab werht dna
.dah seliM sa ylhtooms ro ylteiuq sa ti od dluoc eh kniht t’ndid eh tub
”.worromot pu gnikcip erew ew sehsa ym saw ti fi tihs a evig t’ndluow wonk em tel ev’yeht lla rof ohw
.dedeen yeht sdeb eht no retaw gnitteg diova ot gniyrt
,gnihtemos ekorb eh erofeb elcycrotom eht ffo ,yob nellus eht
.mih ta deffins seliM
,enotswolleY hguorht detuor pu dniw ll'uoy esiwrehtO .tseW nrut uoy erofeb atokaD htuoS otni teG"
.yawa dekool dna sredluohs sih desiar eh etalp a mih dednah eteP dna kcab emac luaP nehW
saw ti ebyam ,rotcod eht saw ti ebyam ,enoemos ,llew ,hO“
,ot deen t’nod uoy dias dah gerG hcihw ot
”.did eh fi esnes ekam d’tI“
.detcepxe eh naht remraw saw tI
...“ ti barg ot dedeen eh dna daeh sih dnuora gnipoows saw rewsna eht ekil ria eht ni sdnah sih devaw naD
thgil fo dnalsi ynit eht edistuo yawhgih sselrats-llits kcalb thgindim eht otni derats dna
.dnal eht fo egde eht ot pu thgir emoc dah seert ehT
".uoy edulcni t'nseod taht dnA
.yllacitamotua sa deneppah dna gniklaw sa larutan sa saw ti gniwollof
.mih deksa seliM nehw ,nayR dias
.emit ni tsuj letom eht dehcaer yehT
setteragic fo stsohg-oga gnol eht dna ,slacimehc gninaelc lairtsudni
”-esol uoy llit kcap ruoy deen uoy hcum woh wonk t’nod uoY“
,edepmats dna cinap ,dekoops teg yehT
kcor yssom eht fo pot eht ot deppoh naD os ,dias seliM
,gninaw saw daehrevo noom ehT
,sehsa eht gniyrrac
tnaw I" .gninetaerht ton dna yhtrowtsurt kool dluow taht yaw a ni gaw ot tseb sih gniod ,dias nayR
.dias nayR ”?taht did deT“
"?od ot tnaw uoy od tahW"
.hguoht ,sparw rednu flow eht tup attog s'eh emityreve steg eh nwod woh tuoba deirrow teg I
.dellats eh emit yreve niaga drawrof mih gnigdun tpek seliM tub
,nrab eht ni no dray eht ni tuo deb dluohs meht fo tser eht rehtehw dna—
,tnorf eht ta rebmem roines tsom ro tsedlo eht tup lliw
”?ereh rewohs a eb annog s’ereht kniht uoY“ ,flesmih
eht …ekil sa raf sa dna
”?ko ,uoy rof krow ot tog t’nseod ti tuB
.yrt lla dluohs ew“
?eb ot dediced I eno eht s’taht noisrev eht ,ekil I noisrev eht ,won ma I em fo noisrev ehT
?thgir ,stekcop ro skcapkcab rieht ni gnihtemos
,detfihs ylluf ,daeh sih denrut eH
d’yhw oS“ ”.epac niksflow a no stup dna knurd dna dekan steg gnikiv emos erehw flowerew fo dnik eht saw
.enozo dna rohcirtep dna nimsoeg htiw nottoc ekil eson s’naD gniffuts ,tew ,dloc
”.ereh deen I ylimaf eht lla toG
.evraH dna deT tem I nehw 02 dna
”.em fo noisrev wen a tsuj saw ti
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”!yats su tel annog s’ehs fi tuo dnif I nehw retteb eb ll’I“
,liart rieht dnif ot yrt ot deen t’ndid eh dna
”.og mih tel ot ereh tuo emac ew
.gninrom eht ni meht dlot eteP
.yal sehtolc tew eht erehw eno eht morf ssorca deb eht ni ,seliM dna nitraM neewteb yal naD won oS
,nrab eht ,esuoh eht ,hcnar eht ni koot taht yaw a ni ,yltnesba ,dnah a devaw ehS ".eteP saw os
.gnissim erew stlobdaed eht tub
.niaga ereht kcab eb naht eid rehtar d'I dna
.daor eht no kcab teg dna
.yawyna yppahnu yrev dna pmad dna dloc saw eh taht hguone gnihsalps saw ti tub ,niar eht ni tuo t’nsaw naD
t’ndid I ,emac segnahc eht nehW“
.doow erab fo eloh tuc yltaen a gnivael devomer ylnaelc neeb d’yeht ,nekorb toN
,sevaw dna gnosdrib fo dnuos eht
”!?detacinummocxe gnieb roF“
.taht ekil mih dreh dluoc seliM woh
”.emoh kcab edir gnol a s’tI
.koolrevo gnikrap pots tser eht htaeneb naeco yerg eht otni kcor htooms a dessot seliM
ylsuoivbo ,evraH—moor tseug eno eht tog ohw fo noissucsid dimA
rewsna ot htuom sih denepo eh nehw dna
.ruof semitemos ,sgel owt no semitemos ,sllih tilnoom eht revo rehtohcae esahc sevlowerew rehto eerht eht dehctaw naD ".ti
.tniop emos ta esiorbuD ettenaeJ fo tnadnecsed a er'yeht dlot steg nawehctaksaS fo tsae flow naidanaC yreve ylbaborp ahcteb I“ .deggurhs gerG
,lleW“ ,dias evraH ”,oN“
”.rof s’pirt siht tahw s’tahT
saw trap tnatropmi eht tuB
.dnE ehT   .ti fo llet ro
,dnuos eht ssorca yrref eht gnikat rof nosaer niam eht saw tahT
eb annog erew sgniht taht ,won flowerew a saw I diaS
.evah yeht revetahw ro gnizitpaB tnediserP fo eciffO
,detfihs ,godpeehs a naht retsaf s'diK"
,ecalp otni kcab nitraM llup ot egru eht thguof
,sseniraew eht ,regnuh eht
smra ’seliM otni denael
,rood eht ot emac sessalg reivaeh dna stoob yvaeh dna riah yerg htiw namow gnikool-dekcohs A
.edisni deraeppasid htob yeht dna ti dekcolnu neht
.pup em dellac eH
,gnikaerb morf eciov sih peek ot deniarts naD
”,rehtona ro yaw eno
,thgil pmalteerts fo elcric a ni tas eH
".stsiruot htiw repmub ot repmub dekcap t'nerew ti fi neve timil deeps elim 51 nmad a sah ecalp taht dna
.tnemom a rof neve ,eb ot detnaw eh gniht tsal eht saw enola tub
.klat mih draeh dah naD tsrif eht saw hcihW
,dehsinab tub suoirotciv eivom eht fo dne eht ta enola yawa klaw oreh eht gnihctaw ekil saw ti
nekcirts ecaf sih
.tsehc s’naD tsniaga ecaf sih deirub nitraM ”.haeY“
,revo lla meht dekool
,ylknalb ,mih gnivig erew seliM dna naD kool eht denruter eteP ”.eb
”?seibar eruc ot denrut nettog tsuj d’uoy erehw ffo yrots eht tfel uoY
”?taht raeh uoy diD“ ”.oN“
.ylnellus ,deffuh luaP ".flesym
”.setats eht ot kcab tog ehs llit flowerew a saw I tuo dnif t’ndid ehS
.yawyna edisni evraH tub enoyna tel t’ndluow uaeruB ehT
,ylhtooms yrev ,pu derruf dna
,revlis hsieulb ot dehcaelb thgilnoom taht sroloc eht llems dluoc eH
.nikpan repap a htiw htuom s’eteP fo renroc eht morf puhctek fo tolb a gnipiw
.nur dluoc uoy naht retsaf uoy drawot devom llaw a fi ,llaw a ekil emac niar ehT
”.deerga I tuB .taht dias uoy“
.ekawa srehto ylno eht erew yehT
.gnihtyreve dna yrarbil eht ot og ot dah ,tenretni eht erofeb saw siht dnA
,kecluV erodoehT fO yenruoJ tsaL ehT“
.detsixe gnihton hcihw dnoyeb tuo sdray derdnuh wef a ylno egde na dah dlrow eht ekil
,no evom ot ydaer saw I emit eht yb dna ,shtnom elpuoc a rof ni su koot deT dna
”.enim rewsna uoy nehw noitseuq ruoy rewsna ll’I“
…m’I“ .dexaler neht
.llems gnirewoprevo eht tuoba mih nraw ot gnihton enod d’yeht dnA .yhctarcs sseL
,ti sdeen evraH swonk doG ,ti deen I
,yawhgih eht dna nagihciM ,ssensselemoh dna ytinamuh ,efil sih fo tser eht taht mih dlot dah enoemos fi dna—
.hguoht tsriht fo gniyd naht retteB .ton ylbaborp
,daeha nur t’nod srebmem citegrene erom regnuoy taht os ecap eht tes ot
.stoob sih dnuora gnilriws saw taht edit gnisir fo os ro hcni eht ni nru eht dial evraH
?neht ,su htiw pu dne uoy did woh oS“
”.gniciton neve tuohtiw tfihs tsrif ym did I .retteb hcum
.yppup denodnaba na ekil seliM dniheb doots
,noitseuq eht gnisserp eno eht llits saw eH
.em brutsid dna pu teg naht rehtar
,saw retaw erehw llems
a saw ehs sdnegel eht ot gnidroccA
,tsael ta ,efas toN .drocer eht rof ,aedi doog a toN
,mih dnuora kcap eht dna pas dna retaw tlas fo llems eht
,em gnivol rof mih knaht ot woh wonk I
”.detacinummocxe ,syas yrots eht ekiL .epoN“
.ylno kcaP snaem taht ,ssenisub kcaP no gniyenruoJ"
”?denrut enoyreve woh ksa yhW .esaelp“
,ekiL .ereht ton s’eh won gnitoof ruo tsol lla ev’eW
.nrab eht ot kcab depol meht fo eerht eht dna
.erofeb yah no tpels reven dah naD ”.yeH“
.enola ,sekih gnireeniatnuom eseht no og ot desu I .hatU ni saw I“
”.ygolaeneg eht pu dekool dna tnew I
.teef fo daetsni swap no tserof eht hguorht nur ot
".su htiw hcuot ni teg ot woh wonk ll'sklof ruoy"
.noitautis dab a fo tseb eht gnikam rof snalp saw ti ,elbatrofmoc evraH edam taht gnihtyna saw ereht fI
.mraw saw ekops eh nehw htaerb sih
”,wonk I naht erom s’tahT“
.dekconk nayR dna evraH
.sesucxe gnikam ton m’I“ .desirprusnu
.erob ,traeh eht reraen edis eht
,tresed eht fo tuo yaw gnol eht lla dnA
.dias seliM ”.ylsuoivbO
ti ot kcil hsiflow fo tnih a tsuj htiw
.stekcop sih ni tsurht sdnah ,dehcnuh sredluohs ,dias nayR
,mih tuohtiw evil ot detnaw I naht erom yna em tuohtiw evil ot tnaw t’ndid eH
”.ecaf ym no noom lluf eht fo thgil eht htiw
.wed detnecs-ssarg teews pu gnikaos ruf
.eciov sih dnuof yllanif naD
”.pup ,noitseuq ym rewsna ot uoy detcepxe I nehw t’nsaw tahT“
!em tib dna erehwon fo tuo emac
,sllems fo hsur gnitacixotni neddus eht ta gnilbmuts rof
,sevlesruo wonk reve ll’ew naht retteb su fo lla wenk deT
,ees ot enon erew ereht
.riaffa na dah yltnerappa ehs ,saw ti revehcihW
emoh doohdlihc a fo erutcip a yldetcepxenu gniees ekil saw ti
”.em ot ,esoht saw eH“
.tey ti od ot ydaer ton er’uoy fi ko s’tI
detniap yarps neeb dah daehsflow gnilrans edurc a hcihw no
.nwod yaw eht no ekops meht fo enoN
"?yawyna ,nottum ti si yhW"
.detfihs yllautca reven uoy sa gnol os tsuj enif saw taht tuB
,etatsretni eht ffo dna syawhgih SU dna sdaorkcab no gniyats
”.uoy era rehtien dna ,erehwyna gniog ton m’I
”…tsuj ot desoppus erew uoY ?nis a saw flowerew a gnieb …os ,tiaw ,tiaW“
,serohs rehto ot ,daor rehtona koot
”.tresed eht ni tuo deid nos rieht dias yehT“ ”?tahW“
.ecno ta lla thgir lla eb attog t’nod uoY“
,dias nayR ",yademos ebyaM"
.esuohmraf eht ees dluoc eno ti morf taht evas
.suonimo elttil a dna ,gnitivni ,tnacav doots rood nepo ehT
,381 dna 63 syawhgih SU neewteb esohc yeht elihw rotom s’ekib sih gnildi ,kcap eht fo tsellams dna tsegnuoy eht gnihctaw seno ylno ehT
.dnal eht morf nelots dah ti sdnalsi ynots eht dnuora dils dna
ro ykrej dna srab nietorp ycnegreme dah lla yeht tub ,siht ni erehwyna gniog s’ydobon
.od ot desoppus saw pirt eht tahw yltcaxe saw taht
,dessap yllanif dah mrots eht taht yas ot ni seson rieht dekop newO dna gerG nehw taht ekil gniyl llits erew yehT .oot did seliM
.daeh s’naD no nihc sih detser newO ,tsehc s’newO no daeh sih dial naD
erehw evil ot yaw a em dewohs tahT
"?thgin eht rof nwod deb ot enoyreve rof tops a gnidnif tuoba ees og ebyam uoy nac ,nitraM“
erodoehT fO yenruoJ
?semit raw livic eht tey ton
.noom lluf eguh a htiw
.eert tsucol delrang eguh a rednu efil ot gnignilc ylerab nwal ssarg a otni
ev’dluow msitpaB laitnediserP“ ,nitraM dias ”,oN“
”.emoh og dna kcab tfihs ot hguone nwod em deklat dna tuo em deffins deT tpecxe ,ecilop eht dellac evah dluow ylbaborp stneraP
.dias apmarG tahw s’taht tsael ta rO“ .deggurhs newO
,deksa neeb d’eh fi ,dias evah dluow naD
.eno siht nwod nrut ylno d’eh fi
.yllacisyhp tsomla ,truh thguoht tsal tahT
”?moor emos htiw gnihtemos ro krap etats a rof tuo eye na peek s’tel ebyam os
.evah dluoc sdrow naht
.sedalb redluohs sih neewteb ot kcen sih fo kcab eht nwod ffurcs eht dna srae s’naD dekorts evraH .derewsna seliM
,meht fo neves eht gnoma tilps ot sdeb ruof erew erehT
ylraelc s’taht edis talf gib eno tog s’ti taht tcaf eht yb llet nac uoy
,tsew eht ot ,noziroh eht no sduolc erew erehT
,em otni nar eh nehw ,gniod emos koot tI
.elpoep ekil kool uoy hcum woh rettam on htaenrednu flow a er'uoy llems nac yeht dna ,trams oot era swoc" ,dias eteP ".swoc
,ekawa ylluftneser llits tub sselpeels ylraelc pu nwohs d'ohw ,luaP dlot gerG
.niaga gnivom saw kcap ehT
.enola og ot dednetni dah evraH
",ekil s'ti tahw wonk ot tnaw llits uoy dna ,esrepsid ot uoy rof semoc emit eht nehW"
”?kcab tog uoy nehw yawa uoy denrut ylimaF“
,degnahc gnihton dna dessap ruoh na flah nehw tuB
.dnoyeb eiriarp fo ecnelis cinaeco etinifni eht dna
”.ti rewsna ot detcepxe I nehw t’nsaw tahT“
.esrow tlef taht dna
”?neht ,ti tnaw t’nod uoY“
.dehgis yllanif newO ”,gnol
.htiw emoc t'ndluoc eh nosaer laer eht saw tahT
”.tog llits ev’I mih fo eceip a
seidob rieht ffo deggof ylwols retaw eht sa thgit naD dleh eH
.tey ti fo og tel ot evah t’nod uoY“
,dias eiluJ ”,detrats kcap ruoy woh s’taht dnA“
elots nayR ”.revef a dah I ,onnud I“ .deksa newO
,srats eht ta pu gnikool rebmemer I
.das eb ot detcepxe dah naD
.meht fo htob revo gab gnipeels eht dellup seliM dna delooc yllanif yeht sa
detelped lla dah ,og ot rewop sih ni saw ti sa riapsed htiw derahs gniod erew yeht tahw taht redrob eht ot esolc sa htiw gniog ,evraH gnitroppus ,evraH ot pu gnidnats fi sa
,trihs a no tup dna sriatspu og luaP taht dna
”?neht ,ydal hctiw eht saw ti uoy llet yeht
”.suoivbo si tser eht sseug I" .nos rieht
.daehrevo latem eht no niar eht fo gnidnuop eht revo elbiduani saw rednuht ehT
.emit emas eht ta tsomla
,senip dekrab-revlis rednels fo swor ot yaw evag tseroF
yb dna nettirw
.smaerd sih rebmemer t’ndid eh ,demaerd eh fI
.taht tnaw I kniht d'yeht yhw teg t'nod I
”.wonk I lla s’taht dnA
na flesmih gnillac saw eh fI“
tsaL ehT“yojne esaelP   .egap trofwolliP sih no sekoj dab dna
.pam a kcehc ot sdaorssorc eht ta deppots
,htiw enod s’nirednaw yM“
,won taht gnirebmemer saw eh yhw nwonk t’ndah naD
.dias naD ”,siht fo draeh reven ev’I“
tnemarcas a eviecer ot mlap a tuo gnidloh repihsrow a ekil nru eht drawot dnah a hcaer eteP dehctaw
”?dias yeht tahw wonk uoY
.seye s’nitraM fo shtped eht ni detcelfer dna sniatruc eht pu til gninthgiL
,rewohs eht htiw snrut koot enoyrevE
rof saw ti tahw wonk t’ndid eh neht erised a ekil saw ti fi
.kcab nettog tsuj dah nitraM dna evraH erehw sekib fo enil eht fo dne rehto eht ta gniddon ,dias seliM
hcihw ,deniar dah ti emit tsal eht morf sseug I
.nedlo yllaer ekil ,semit nedlo ni kcaB“
.smra s’seliM ni thgin lla tpels eH
.naD ot derrucco gnihtemos ,tol gnikrap eht gnissorc erew yeht sA
,htab mraw a erew yeht ekil—
meht neewteb gnihton neeb dah ereht
.yawa ti ekat ot yrt ot tuoba saw enoemos deirrow saw eh ekil egakcap eht gnidloh saw eH ”.erac
.tnalp deretaw a ekil kcab emac erusopmoc siH
taht“ deksa naD ”,gnithgifni eht taht saW“
,deppans edisni seriw eht
peelsa nellaf d’I
draykcab eht ni peels ot tnew dna tuo tnew I os dna
.deid evah llew sa thgim I taht gnikniht ,saw I ereht
.em rof eno dah eh ylimaf a dna emoh a dedeen I nehw esuaceb
”?hguoht ,gninrut uoy ot pu dda taht seod woH“ ,detcejbo naD
.esolc deldduh ,doof gnisnes ,kcap eht fo tser ehT .did naD
?ti si ,raf taht ton s’tI .naeco eht ot
”,lleW“ ”.tif t’nseoD
ffo ti dekcik d’yeht dna ,teknalb a naht yretslohpu ekil erom tlef dna
gerG taht derevocsid kcap eht fo tser eht woh dna
.deksa naD ”?taht s’tahW“
”.ereht hguor tib a gnikooL ?ko uoY“
.suoivilbo dna sraet ni rehtohcae gnidloh erew yeht tub ,tsesolc erew newO dna nitraM .dnuora dekool seliM
.detiaw meht fo tser ehT
,eerf ,nwo ym no saw I
,lwoh ot ,llems ot ,tfihs ot thguat gnieb ot ,erofeb ot kcab mih deggard lla ti
…tub nac I fi wonk t’nod I dna
.meht ni sseniraew etarepsed fo rekcilf taebtraeh-a-naht-ssel a saw ereht dna seye s’naD thguac seliM
taht em ecnivnoc ot deT rof
”.srewoP tniaS sih htiw sevlow otni meht gninrut dna meht gnisruc htrow saw ti thguoht silataN tniaS yltnerappa tub
,kcab gnikohc neeb d’uoy sgniht eht lla leef dna
,tnetsisni ylbavommi saw eh nialpxe t’ndid eh nosaer emos rof dna aedi sih saw ti esuaceb seliM
.taes regnessap eht ni snaej dedaf ni dik gnikool nellus a htiw
”.ti yas uoy raeh attog I“ ”.ko ,haeY“
,rood nrab eht ot delian ,ngis timil deeps nelots eht ta deddon daetsni dna
,was I gniht tsal eht eb annog erew yeht erus
,ylizal ,seliM dessik naD
esaelp I erehwyna
.thgir lla saw ti ,ymene na regnol on ,melborp a regnol on saw ssendas ehT .derit regnol oN
.yah fo dekeer taht tserof a ni
,detaname noitats sag eht taht
”.uoy fo lla ot emoh em thguorb eh neht dnA
,ereht teg ew ecno tuB
alallagO fo htron hcnar eht ot ni dellup d’yehT
,yevraH dewollof yehT
.edis eht ot deppils yltnelis neht wollof ot meht rof derutseg
.nwot txen eht ot edir a ebyam ,tuodnah a rof gnipoh tsuj saw I
”.sseug I“ ,deunitnoc naD
”,eruS“ .evraH dias ”,haeY“
.emoh kcab su teg annog t’nsi ti dna
.dias newO ”.tsenoh eb ot ,erus %001 ton m’I“   ”.htrow
.trapa llef kcap eht fi tluaf ym eb d’ti yas d’ahpla eht ,ti rof ffo em llet d’eh emit yrevE“
,dias d’ehs ,esoppus I
.reh ot ton hguoht ,noitseuq s'efiw sih derewsna eteP ".gnidreH"
,nees eb d’yeht ebyaM
.yllautca ,trapa llef kcap tsal ym snosaer eht fo eno saw tI“
”?flowerew a uoy ekam msitpaB laitnediserP seod woH“
.su fo lla fO .su fo tseb eht saw eH“ dias gerG
,sdoow roirepuS ekaL eht ni egdol eht ni kcab pu ekaw ot gniog saw eh dnoces yna ekil tlef eh taht
?thgir ,flowerew a morf neeb osla evah tsum etib eht taht serugif
,rotaluclac yranigami na revo gninnur sregnif ,desuap gerG
,ybraen erots ecneinevnoc ruoh-42 a saw ereht dias pam eht
.yah eht dednim regnol on eh taht hguone derit saw eH
,feirg nwo rieht hcae htiw regnol on meht gnivael ,rehtegot deloop gniveirg riehT
”?uoy od ,deT dna evraH dna em neewteb yrotsih eht wonk yllaer t’nod owt uoY“
.daeh sih koohs eteP
?pup ko uoy erA“ ,detuohs
.em ot gnineppah saw tahw aedi on dna noitamrofsnart tsrif ym hguorht yawflah ,gnicar traeh ,thgindim tuoba pu ekow I daetsnI
.htrow s’ti tahw rof ,od llitS“
.ekil yllaer saw ti tahw ksa ot detnaw I"
.rood ssalg eht ot ecaf sih desserp nayR
noitcerid emas eht ni saw ti
.tfihs tsrif ym ta deracs tog I nehw smra sih ni em dleh eH
.daeh sih koohs seliM
”-evah ton thgim yehT
.wonk reven ll’I won dna ksa t’ndid I dna
”,wonk dluohs enoemos esuaceB“
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
.ti no tca ot derit oot dna dloc oot llits saw eh
.gnihton ro riaf tset siht
”.niaga nees teg reven dna gnissim og
.enil edit hgih eht llems dluoc yeht erehw thgir doots dah yehT ”.siH
.enoemos nrut ot syaw reltneg
”.kcap eht ot kcab mih teg steL“ .evraH dias
,sretspmud morf gnitaE .gniog tpek
.siht hguorht edir dluoc enoyna woh enigami t’ndluoc eh esuaceb yltsoM
.yrd ot tuo meht yal ot esle erehwon saw ereht dna tew erew sehtolc s’enoyreve esuaceb
.llew sa esle gnihtemos saw eh taht draug ffo mih nekat dah tI
revetahw ot etirw ot reh ot derrucco evah t’ndluoW .sseug I
.gnivom tuohtiw tsomla dna etarepsed dna ydeen emac eh neht
?eno tuohtiw erutsap htuos eht dnuora gninnur gniod neeb eh dah kceh eht
,enog s’eh gnittegrof rof flesym ta yrgna gnitteg
neht dna ,ereht eb ot mih gnitcepxe flesym gnihctac dna srenroc dnuora gnimoc peek I
.seye sih ni elbigel ylbakatsimnu saw tnemevaereb ksam namuh sih gniraew t’nsaw eh taht won dna
,rehcaet htam deriter a ,renwo suoiverp eht rof neeb dah taht denialpxe eteP tub
”.thginot evraH htiw m’I tub ,ecin s’tahT“
,thgindim retfa gnol ton tniop emos tA
,gninrut morf em TPEK
”.mih fo trap a pu gnivig ekil sleef ti gnillet dnA
”.mih retfa teg s’teL ?rof gnitiaw uoy er’tahW“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.yawa gniknirhs naD ot tcaer t’ndid seliM
,saw reh yrram ot hguone bmud flow eht erehw reh deksa nitraM dna
.mih htiw od ot s’ti esuaceb ,drah …s’tI“
.edisni VT eht ta detniop neht
,yltnettimretni gnizod
.ton spahreP .htgnerts sih
.epols yssarg eht revo gniohce slwoh eht ot netsil ot gniklat deppots evraH
.gnirewoprevo ssel saw yah fo llems eht nrab eht edistuo tub ,nees eb ot erehwon saw luaP
.skrowerif morf gnidih sgod ekil rehtohcae ot gnulc yeht drawretfA
".eno eb ot dneterp ot evah t'ndluohs I .nosrep lamron a ton m'I
”.htiw revo ti teg ew renoos eht ,ereht teg ew renoos eht os ,gard a eb annog s’atihciW ekil sdnuoS .nom’c woN“
.saw ti naht retfos tol a eb ot ti tcepxe mih edam dah snootrac dlO
.eteP tem reve dah naD emit dnoces eht ylno saw sihT .eteP dias
”?yaw taht ti tuoba klat uoy nac woH“
.yad rehtona gnivil fo ssensseltniop eht
”,retal ti nialpxe ll’I“
floWcaM boR
.bmuht sih htiw draeb sih rednu debbur yltneg ,nihc sih detfil dna keehc s’naD dehcuot eH
.denihw eh ”,siht od nac I fi onnud I“ .ffo ekorb eh
.won rof tsael tA .em rof gnikrow
.mih fo hcni yreve ot yaw sti dnif ot deganam dah
.kcap ruoy ni ekil gniviL"
.tsael ta ,slufhtuom elpuoc a teg ot enoyreve rof
dnaH" .llirg eht morf yttap a detfil eH ".etar
,ti nepo evraH dehctaw
,efil ym fo tser ehT
,smoortser erew ereht dias ngis eht esuaceb pots tser eht otni dellup d’yehT
,esuohhcnar eht morf noitcerid etisoppo eht
.od ot desoppus saw yenruoj eht tahw saw siht ebyaM
,tol gnikrap eht saw taht dnaletsaw tlahpsa eht ni edahs ylno eht saw hcihw ,hcnarB tsewdiM
”.seibar dah I retal htnom a dna …ti no sdiadnab emos ,tnatcefnisid emos tup tsuj I os
.etalp sih morf yawa dnah s’nayR dekcams evraH ”.oN“ ”?ew od ,ni og
.elddirg a no gnikrap ekil saw ti raey eht fo ssenetal eht etipsed dna
,nis a saw I thguat saw I“
.mlac ot nageb eh llit tsehc dna daeh s’nitraM dekorts naD ”!ko s’ti ,yeh
,tnecs fo tuo ton tub
”…ot uaeruB eht ot og ll’I“
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
redrah ti edam tsuj yeht
.niaga tnelis neeb d’yeht neht dna
.devver senigne ehT .nesohc saw yawhgih A
.rewop eht tuo dekconk mrots eht nehw ecnetnes eht hguorht yawflah saw nitraM -tuo kconk t’nseod mrots eht epoh tsuj I
,moor tew-ssel ehT
.sllihtoof eht otni dellup yeht sa dniheb morf mih no seye s’seliM tlef eH
,srae ym gnikorts tsuj
.gnitiaw erew sekib rieht lla erehw kced rac eht morf pu spets latem eht no gnar stoob s’evraH
,deksa dna senigne eht fo dnuos eht revo draeh t’ndah eh dedneterp eh os ,rehtie ,deksa neeb dah eh noitseuq eht rewsna ot tnaw t’ndid osla eh tuB
.citehtap adnik s’tI“
,sffilc worran neewteb noynac gnidniw fo sruoh decaf rellevart eht gniwonk ,fi sa saw tI
…ekil morF .cebeuQ ni erolklof morf uoraG puoL suomafni na saw ehs
,ti ot hguone esolc ro ,nwot eht ni sthgin owt gnidneps ta gnikool ylbaborp er’eW .taht ekil gnihtyna ro tol gnikrap eht ni ti od uoy tel t’now ylbaborp yeht dna ,tiaw ot evah lla’Y
”,em ot neppah gnihctaw tsuj saw I gnihtemos saw ti ekil efil ym evil ot desu I“
.denethgit htuom sih dna ,ekib s’evraH ta decnalg eH
devorp ti semit eerht tub ,tsol d’yeht thguoht naD semit eerhT .flah a dna ruoh na rof mrots eht decar yehT
.revetahw ro ,11 raeY
.seye rehto denepo dna seye namuh sih desolc eh evid hgih eht morf flesmih gniworht ekil neht ,htaerb peed a koot ,taorht sih dnuora tsif dehcnelc ruos a ekil tlef tahw dewollaws eH
.taht ekil gnihtemos gniyas ,meht ekil eb d’tahT
.ereh mrots eht tuo tiaw ot dedeen yeht gnidulcnoc erew yeht sseug dluoc eh tub
”rehtorB kcaP dna
”.desufer eH“ ,dias evraH
”.mih ot rucco d’taht gniht fo tros eht s’tI“ .dias seliM
dedaf ylwols taht evird levarg ediw eht ni dekrap dna—
.doog os tlef ti ,ytpme krap eht dnuof dna ereh tog yeht ecnis semit ytfif ti enod evah tsum eh rettam t’ndid ti dna
,dnabsuH devoleB ,redaeL
yzarc s’eh evorp nac I woN
em evas dluow taht gniht ylno eht saw ti wenk DNA flowerew a wenk taht rotcod a dah
.eb ot detnaw I tahW
.dias seliM ”.ko s’tI“
.won tsenrae ni nugeb dah thgin ehT
.gninthgil teehs snretnal o kcaj ekil til sdnuom sulumuc ,denworc livna ,sayalamih kcalb fo trapmar a saw tI
”.seod esle enoyna fi rO“
,kcab gnillup erofeb
”-saw deT .t’ndluow I ro
,suovren rof edam seitic gib ,llew yrev ni erew uoy eno eht wenk uoy sselnU
,esnes ekam ot rewsna eht detcepxe dah naD
"?nur dna tuo flow ot thgin ta tuo gnikaens neeb uoy gnol woH"
.eciov sih ni enihw elttil a ,gniyas saw luaP
s’taht ,wonk I ylno terces a ti peek I sa gnol sA
…eb dluow rewsna eht diarfa syawla saw I tub ,mih deksa evah dluohs I
.kcab saw kcap eht fo tser eht erofeb
,tuo dnif neve ot snoitseuq gniksa fo sraey koot tI
.roolf eht evah sevaw eht fo dnuos eht tel eh tub
,evraH derewsna ,taht wolla ot gniog erew yeht yaw on saw erehT
.niaga ecnartne eht ot denrut seliM
,seliM dias ,dluohs ew ,seliM dias ,haeY
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,won aksarbeN otni pu ,tsew gnidaeh llits ,niaga htron denrut yehT
,eromyna ,flow a gnieb yllaer em tub ydobyna tuoba mih eveileb neve I fi onnud I
”.flow a otni nrut reven uoy dna
”!ma I sa dalg sa toN
.gniyarts morf yna tneverp dna
,elbakatsimnu saw eciov ’seliM ni tsugsid eht ”’,ahplA‘
.snoitpo rehto fo tol a evah t’ndid eh tub ,erusnu gnileef tuoba gnituohs egnarts tlef tI
,ecitslos remmus tsomla saw tI
,esle gnihtyna leef ot gnidnamed dna
.noitautis dab eht tuoba kniht ton ot
.ekib sih revo gel eno worht ot tuoba ,desuap nayR ”,tiaW“
,delworg dah nayR
,troprac eht rednu meht evael dna sekib eht revoc ot meht rof gnituohs ,tuo denael nayR dna denepo rood eht neht tuB
.erehwyna pu dne thgim eH
,deb eht no gniyrd sehtolc eht tuohtiw
”.meht fo eno tsomla saw I“
.evaheb ,ssa uoy ,larenuf a si siht ,dias dna mih dekcams ehs dna
pu emac nus eht llit
".hcum yb ton tub ,esrepsid ot gnuoy oot elttil a er'uoy" ,dias gerG
.no sehtolc sih dellup dna flesmih deird naD sa looc saw thgin nepo ehT
,yenruoj eht fo dne eht ot su teg annog t’nsi ti tub ,niaga lliw dna ti deen lla ew
.tfel su fo owt eht tsuJ .deddon dah eteP dna
yroeht tnerruc ym oS
.aha ,thguoht I ,flowerew a saw eh su dlot deT nehw oS
.seipoc ekam og ot deen uoy ro
,etam reh ,eert tsucol detsiwt eht
.gnol t’nsaw nwod liart ehT
.won saw eh erehw saw taht dnA
.krad s’ti won ,yawa setunim ytriht ot ytnewt tuoba ylekil s’dnuorgpmac tseraen
.mih tuohtiw era ew ohw tuo erugif ot niyrt lla er’eW“
.tesnus neeb llits dah ti dessorc snoynac eht erehw ereh tub
.ereh m’I sa gniees ,eb ot evah d’ti naem I .sseug I ,rehtaf ym htiW
.on yllacinhcet ,lleW“ ”?eno eb ton...“
.tnavelerri eb ot tuo denrut dah tI
.nruter fo ytilibissop lla dnoyeb tsol si tcejbo sti swonk taht
,maets emos ffo wolb ,ycavirp emos htiw ecalp a evah rehtar d’I eciohc eht neviG ?swonk ohW“
”.hsinif dluoc eh erofeb uoy htiw em ekat dias evah dluow I dna
eht ni gniyalp neeb dah taht troper rehtaew eht dnuof yeht llit slennahc hguorht deppilf newO dna ,VT a dah
.eulb swodahs eht lla detnit dah yks eht gnillif roloc nomlas ehT
.meht dniheb niaga ti dekcol ehS
,parcs tsevrah htiw derettil sdleifnroc
,llems yb ,dezilaer ylno dna
,edahs fo parcs eht ni dih meht fo eerht eht oS
.noisrev eno naht erom ni ,erofeb yrots eht draeh ev’ohw ecneidua na fo
,evraH dna deT ot did I tahw tuoba garb og ,gninrom eht ni pu teg d’I“
”,ecnahc eht meht evig t’ndiD“ .dias gerG
”?taht yas uoy diD“
.rethgil leef did eh tub ,das ssel leef t’ndid eH .dias naD
.oga gnol oot toN
”,yaw lausu eht saw ti thguoht I .ko ,llew ,hO“
”?tnirptoof s’flow a morf knard uoy
.mih fo edis rehtie no esolc deldduc dna
siht eziromem flesmih ekam ot woh nwonk evah dluow eh erus t’nsaw eH
,esruoc fo ,kcap ym lla evol I“
sottorg dna sffilc nekorb eht hguorht dehsols tI
",yademos ,lliw uoY"
,meht dniheb yats t’ndluow nwad ehT
.saw ti esohw dias evah t’ndluoc naD
,wonk ot uoy tnaw t’nod I taht ton s’tI .onnud I“
,ylniatrec ,yppah toN
.thgin eht fo tsom eevel eht ni trevluc a ni gnidih pu dnuow I
dluoc I taht gniciton ylneddus neht dna
”.ofni pu gid ot gniyrt ,ffo gninnur syawla saw I woh ekil t’ndid yehT
.eb ot detnaw I ohw tuoba kniht em edam deT“
.thgin tsrif eht gniklat ekil hcum leef dluow ydoboN
.dias evraH ”,ti teg I“
.pu deeps ti deciton t’ndah eh yhw derednow dna ,niaga wols gnihtaerb sih tlef naD
”-dna niaga mih gnitcepxe m’I dna niaga nettogrof ev’I renroc txen eht ot teg I emit eht yb snaem tsuj taht tub ti tuoba gnikniht morf em tcartsid ot gnihtemos tnaw I dna
,moor tnorf eht ni hcuoc eht no
.kcab mih dellup dna redluohs eht yb mih debbarg evraH
,kcap eht fo tser eht morf ,rumrum lareneg eht saw erehT
,nruter reven dluoc uoy hcihw ot
gniod ni detseretni saw I ekil t’nsaw ti esuac ,dnif dluoc I flowerew a emoceb ot yaw suolucidir tsom eht pu dekool I oS
.tsomerof saw newO ”?gnorw gnihtemoS“
.dniheb morf mih dnuora depparw smra s’nayR
”.nrut rieht s’ti nehw rewsna annog er’yeht woh no gnikniht s’enoyrevE
”?taht mih llac uoy od yhW“
.mih ta derats htob yehT
.deen uoy tahw s'taht fi ,elihw a rof uoy htiw nur si od nac ew tahW"
,senip tnatsid eht drawot sepols eht pu seohce eht gnisahc dna gnilwoh dna gnikrab rof
dnuof I sdrocer eht fo emoS
.tniop emos ta daD ot ti dessap moM emussa ot evaH
.dellac ydobemos ffirehs eht morf nur ot dah ,revo sgniht gnikconk ,gnikrab ,gnilwoh ,sukcur a edaM
.ecurps fo swor yb dessorcssirc
.gniklat detrats d’eh
.gninrom eht ni ylrae yaw ,riovreser eht fo egde eht ta tuo gniggoj saw I
.peelsa llef dna ,gerG dna nayR neewteb yal eH
saw ti ,ti yas ot emit a reve saw ereht fi dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ralimis ylgnibrutsid dellems stserof eht tub ,tnereffid erew esoht ,sniatnuom eht toN
.mra eno rednu egakcap a gnidloh saw eH
,mottob eht ta elddup ynit a saw erehT
.knalf sih dna mra sih neewteb wolloh eht otni kcab nayR dellup ylmrif tub yltneg dah newO
,dniw eht ni gnireviuq sreksihw sih leef dluoc eh
,naD ta drah dekool seliM ”.deT fO“ ”?mih fO“
.denihw nitraM ”,yrroS“
,senilrewop gnipoows fo muiriled revef a demees lla ti—
”.enim rewsna d’uoy ,noitseuq ruoy derewsna I fi dias uoY“ ”?tahw lleW“
”?thginot uoy htiw enoemos deen …uoy oD“ ”.sknahT
.mih dniheb thgir ni deklaw nayR nehw depmuj eH
.og ot ydaer ereht srepap eht lla dah yeht ,enif saw tI“
s’erehT .t’ndid eH .dehgual dna
”?tuoba gniklat owt uoy er’tahW“ ”?uoy ro ,em“
.nam doog a neeb t’ndah eh fi
”?yrt dluoc I“ ,dias evraH
dnats ot dedeen yeht
.tfihs ot raelc lla eht evag evraH llit tiaw ot od dluoc naD lla neeb dah tI
”.yletarebiled ,flesym denrut I“
taht fo hguone did
,kcen sih fo edis eht dessik nayR
d’woH‘ .ksa ot tsrif eht saw seliM
”?lleW“ .s’deT saw tI
,sraey elpuoc a rof tihS a gniviG toN namuhartxE fo uaeruB eht fo ydotsuc ni saw I
,floWcaM boR yb ”rehtorB kcaP dna
.thgin eht otni yawa gnicaf ,deppots newO
reh ot detaler t’nsaw I tuo dnuof dnA“ .delkcuhc eH
”?eh diD .yhw wenk eh thguoht eh dias evraH“
,evraH ot elbissop sa esolc sa yats ot egru eht thguof naD
”.nis a sa detnuoc ti nehw saw TAHT
.erohs ykcor eht fo egde eht ta evraH ediseb pu deppets newO
”.niaga mih tsniaga peelsa llaf ot teg reven ll’I dnA
.meht ta dekrab evraH "!emit a ta enO"
,edis rehtie no seliM dna naD
”.yawyna pu wohs smotpmys ecnO“
.sih erew yeht esuaceb meht devol I
.alusninep elohw eht fo pit tsehtruf eht saw pam eht no mih dewohs newO hcihw
”,meht dnif reve d’I kniht t’ndid I nehw neve ,ylimaf dna emoh rof gnikool efil elohw ym tneps I“
,seldeen enip eht fo edisrednu eht no retaw eht ffo gnitcelfer nus noonretfa etal fo roloc eht leef dluoc naD .elif elgnis
,deT fo rednimer a saw noitasnes yrevE .ti rewsna ot dnes ot detnaw eh taht lwoh eht dna eltsihw niart tnatsid eht raeh dluoc eh
”?su htiw yaw eht fo tser eht gnimoc uoY“
.tserof laer eht saw ,hguoht ,aes eht fo edis rehto eht nO
”?saw ti su llet uoy dluow tahw“
.evila tresed taht fo tuo em tog flow ehT“
.thgis fo tuo dna daor eht nwod erew yeht llit hctaw ot etag eht ta deyats dah tub ,derewolg dah luaP
.gninrut s’etamkcap hcae tuoba noitseuq lautibah sih gnitterger-kcom dna ,truh-kcom ,dias seliM
.resolc dna resolc emac naeco eht hcihw hguorht
.laer kool t’ndid tI
”.dah reve I stnerap ot gniht tsesolc eht erew yeht tuB
.deksa t’ndah eh noitseuq eht gnirewsna
.uoy fo lla rof mih knaht d’I
.dluoc eh tub ,evah dluoc namuh a fi wonk t'ndid eH
,dik flow a eldnah ot woh wonk t’ndid tsuj ehs tub tseb reh did ehs taht kcap tsal eht llet ot desu I
yas ot emit dah ylno eh dna ,nekcarb yrd hguorht gnihsarc swap fo dnuos eht saw ereht neht tub
kcuts eb annaw t'nod I fi snaem ti tahw kniht ot tnaw t'nod yeht esuac ti timda annaw t'nod yehT" .luaP dekrab
.mih tuohtiw ,ma I ohw erus gnieb ton peek I …tsuj I .enif m’I
.gof fo sekaw tnelubrut hguorht gnidir mih tfel dna retaw hguorht staobdeeps ekil ti nrot dah mih fo daeha sekib ehT
”?pu gid uoy did ofni tahw ,oS
.s’nitraM dna s’gerG dna s’newO dna s’nayR saw ti
”.pup ,kO“ ”.esimorP“
,nwod saw nus ehT
.ni pu werg I kcap eht ot em dessap yeht llit
sehcnuah sih no gnittauqs saw luaP hcaorppa ot detrats eh tnemom eht tub ,flow gnuoy eht ediseb taes a ekat ot devom gerG
”?niaga ,ew era erehW“
”,tub ,peels ot elba eb ll’I hcum woh onnuD
,skcor eht fo pot eht ta seert eht ot kcab dellup yehT
,mih ta gnikool seliM leef dluoc naD dna ,won saw ti tahw saw won dnA
.gnihtyna dnatsrednu t’ndid ew ,sdik bmud erew eW
.feiler a saw tahT
.taob eht rednu dekcus retaw neerg krad eht erehw tops emas eht ta derats dna
,eurt s’ti esuaceB“
”-wonk t’nod I taht fo og tel I fi dna ,mih ot ewo I ma I gnihtyrevE“ .ylteiuq
,maerc eci morf fi sa sreicalg yb sniatnuom eht fo tuo depoocs ylnaelc ,sevruc htooms gnol neeb dah ni dellup d’yeht sa krap ehT
”?uoy ssim yeht kniht uoy oD“
,derewsna seliM ”,yllautcA“
.smoor dah yehT .mih wollof neht
.erus m’I ,wenk deT“ .dias seliM
”pup ,ti tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’uoy wonk I“
.tekcop ym ni eton a tfel yeht
.aes eht revo gnittes nus fo revils tsal eht no dexif erew seye sih tub
.elttaeS fo lwarps eht fo htron deyats d’yehT
.txen eht rO .txen eht rO
,dediced eh ,retteb tlef ti esruoc fo dnA
,srepap eht ngis ot dah eh esuaceb evraH
.teef sih ta naD dna mih ediseb seliM htiw—mad eht
,ot tsuj owt ro etunim
.erofeb erew yeht revetahw ,msi-
,luaP teg nitraM taht gnidnamed saw eiluJ ,elbat cincip eht dnoyeB ".sevlowerew
elpoep rof eveirg ot gnivah tuohtiw hguone krow s’deT rof gniveirG“
dnuos eht gnola htron gniog morf denrut eniltsaoc eht gniwollof yawhgih cipmylo eht erehw
!huH“ ”.htrow s’ti tahw rof ,uoy denrut deT dalg yllaer m’I“
”?eh t’ndid ,uoy denrut deT“
ees neve dna raeh dna llems
,erusnu mih edam hcihw
,pal sih no daeh ym htiw
”?thgir ,ylimaf dlo ruoy morf gniraeh llits ton er’uoy ,oS“
,tuhs seye sih dehcnelc eH .deT yB
,seybdoog tsal delwoh yehT
.htuom s’flowerew rehto eht otni sdrow sih ehtaerb ot fi sa ,s’seliM ot daeherof sih desserp eH
!efil nmad ym lla godpeehs gniyalp
.noom eht ta gnirats saw seliM tub
.won saw eH ”?ekawa uoY !yeH“
,sdnats thgin eno fo tibah a edam eh sseug I tub ,saw eh ohw
.thgir saw eh ,riaf eb oT“
,gniht noziboL elohw eht tuoba wonk t’ndid moM“
”?uoy dellac deT tahw s’taht esuaC ?neht pup rehtohcae llac uoy ,oS“
.ti dias dah eh fi luaP ot derettam evah t'ndluow ti wenk dna taht yas ot woh aedi tsethgils eht dah t'ndah eh dna
evah ot hguone nwod emac I emit eht yB“
.tnemom eht ta eno evah t’ndid eh fi neve
,llew sa semoc eh ereh esuaceb rehtie gerG won ro ,taht nayR llet t’nod tub
?gnitfihs ecno reve tuohtiw saw apmarG sa dlo sa teg enoyna dluoc woh esuac
.tius a ni enoemos ot gniklat
”.erus ,won su rof ,lleW“
,dias uoy ekil tuB“
.sredluohs sih dnuora mra eno tup evraH ”.nam ,ko s’tI“
redluohs sih degdun nayR
”?siht fo draeh reven ylsuoires ev’uoY .noziboL a gnieb dellac s’tI
,emit siht ,tsehc s’naD tsniaga delruc seliM
.dnim ym fo tuo etsat eht fo yromem eht teg ot elba eb ot gniog reven m’I evil I sa gnol sa dna ,dum tog tsuj I erofeb dluoc I tahw pu depruls I
,tsehc sih morf pu dekool dna ,swalc tlef naD
taht tub ,meht ot gnola ti devom ,rebmem wen rehtona neeb d’ereht fi emankcin eht gnisu deppots ev’dluow eh ebyaM .hcum os rehtegot kcuts ,emit emas eht tuoba kcap eht denioj ew ecnis“ ,dias seliM
.ffo deliart eH ”…eh
,elbisivni saw meht dnuora tserof eht fo tsoM
”?em fo nuf gnikam uoy erA“
!ti yaS“ ”!nom’c ,nayR“
.eson sih hguorht dehgis seliM
.snworbhsah fo lufhtuom a hguorht gerG dias
.smra s’rehtohcae ni meht tfel dna tsud daor eht htiw yawa dehsaw skcab s’rehtohcae gnibburcs fo esneterp ynA
,meht fo lla rof hguone egral ylerab
,esuops lagel saw I .mih tcelloc oT“
.yawhgih tresed a ffo gnimoc egarim taeh ekil elbisiv saw tfihs ot ton mih gnikat saw ti troffe ehT
.temleh sih no dellup naD
.ytpme tsomla saw dnuorgpmac ehT
?pots annog s’ti nehw ekil esnesnon raeh ot stnaw ohW !deen ew ofni eht s’taht
,tiaW“ ”.tnirptoof s’flow a saw
os su gnikat s’tahw gnirednow eb annog
.liart eht fo pot eht ta tol gnikrap eht ni kcab
.ot no dloh ot mrif dna elbats gnihtemos ti edam tI
.tsim looc fo snieks gnisir otni sdleif dna daor eht no retaw eht lla denrut ti dna
enola redael saw eh won ,sih yleritne—kcap sih fo slwoh gniohce eht ni gnikaos ,dias evraH
esolc woh saw taht esuaceb ,hcaer s’smra nihtiw dettauqs seliM dna naD
,meht dehcaer d’yeht ecnis reve sniatnuom eht dniheb neeb dah nus ehT
,noom lluf a dna ,yadirF a eb annog saw taht dna
.mih evol em gnittel rof
.ot desu I ekil mih htiw pu peek t'nac I
.esnes on edam ti fi neve
”.detacilpmoc elttil a s’tI“
”.tnereffid kool ot srats eht detcepxe I“
”.daor eht no kcab teg ot emiT“
.yawhgih eht otno kcab ,eno yb eno ,ffo koot enil eht ni daeha rehtruf srehto eht sa ,gnildi srotom ,seliM ediseb detiaw naD
tsuj“ ,dias naD ”,oN“
.nus eht dnuora dehcaer mrots eht fo sregnif tsomreppu eht nehw neerg ylegnarts denrut thgil ehT
.enilerohs eht morf seye sih desiar ylerab nitraM
.noziroh dna retaw tub
,srats eht ot desopxe ruf ylleb ,kcab sih no dexaler evraH
,mih degguh seliM ”.pup ,yrrow t’noD“
,rehtaeh dna ssarg trohs ni detaoc won
”.pup ,nagihciM morf raf TAHT ton er’eW“
,ynapmoc gninim emos rof gnikrow saw ehs dias
”.niaga ti yas ot notgnihsaW ot kcab yaw eht lla og ot deen I sseug t’nod I dna ,desrepsid I nehw eybdoog dias I
”.sey dias I taht gnihtyna
.sih dessorc htap ym ecnahc yb tsuj dna ,sselepoh dna sselemoh saw I“
”.oot eno otni em nrut ot mih gniksa saw I flowerew a saw eh em gnillet enod saw eh dnoces eht tub
dlihc htneves eht er’uoy fI“
.gnol tiaw t’ndiD .detiaw tsuj I“
.noziroh eht ot yawhgih eht morf thgis ni gnihton saw ereht tuB
.ruof no desimorpmoc yllautneve dna
.retaw eht ni neeb dah tahw gnirednow ,gnikahs dna hsirevef thgin taht tneps I
.knurd tlef eH .ffo deliart eH
.esiwrehto em thguat taht eno eht saw eH
.tuo dial sllordeb ,pu denil erew sekiB
.emit ni tsuj flesmih thguac naD
.hguoht ,mih rof hguone doog saw taht dediced eH .esnes nommoc
.worros htiw dezinomrah taht gnihtemos erew ti fi sa ,das sa
,sniatnuom eht gnihcaorppa meht dnuof dah yad gnisir eht fo taeh ehT
.htaenrednu sexob egnaro dna der eht dna enil eulb detarres eht htiw pam eht ees dluoc eh tub ,ti daer ot yawa raf oot saw naD
.epahs flow eht ot no dloh ot hcum oot tsomla saw ti
,thgis fo tuo erew gerG dna nayR .seye laer siH
,ereht spots adnik yrots eht ,yawynA
.mih dlot dah deT gnihtemos saw ti tub
.nosrep tnereffid a yllaretil saw I dna ,oga emit gnol a saw tI
nus gnittes eht dna
.ti pilf ot ton dediced dna alutaps eht htiw sregrub nottum eht fo eno dekop eteP
,taht dedeen llits I“
,kcap sih fo trap eb dluoc I ,em denrut eh fi taht dias eh si srettam tahW
,yawa denrut dah eteP dna
,srorrim htiw detaoc neeb dah yeht fi sa ecafrus tew gninetsilg yreve ffo dnuora lla detcelfer ti
,kcab em gnidloh gnihton dna daor nepo eht
.repmihw a otni denrut lworg eht dna delworg dna tsud eht dekcik eH
.eromyna tol gnikrap eht ees t’ndluoc eh neht dna ,rood letom eht fo tnorf ni doots taht
.sevlowerew elbatirri
t’ndid yeht ,elbuort ekam t’ndid yehT .emit drah a em evig t’ndid yehT
yltsenoh dna ylpmis erom hcum
"?ajdluow snub fo etalp eht em
,htuom sih denepo eH
”-dnegel eht ot gnidrocca ot desu yeht“ ,seliM detrats ”,lleW“ ”?taht od yehT“
,enola kcab ti edam evah t'ndluoc naD taht toN
,meht hguorht dehsalf ekib sih emit yreve—
,detfihs uoy sa nur ot gnitrats rof
.ti nettog d’I fi
”!nekahs laer kool uoY
.krad tnew ti dna
.siht ekil dekool evah dluow ti
”.tnaw I gniht tsal eht si enolA“
,emit emas eht ta rehtohcae dnuora gnilbmuts flah ,snrut gnikat flah
,yawa dellup ,pu dekohc gerG
.guh eht otni kcab mih llup did naD woN
”.sseug ot elba eb ll’yeht kniht I“
.eb ll’ti srepap lleh eht revetahw ngis tel ll’yeht eno ylno eht m’I os
.keehc sih dehcuot seliM
.erohs eht ot nwod klaw eht rof detfihs lla
dednetni yllacificeps ,ecalp a dengised dah enoemos fI
otni dereggats I RE eht ylikcuL
".elihw A"  .deksa nayR
.retaw fo spord htiw dedaeb niatruc saw ti ekil
.erofeb reh tem t’ndah ohw seno ylno eht erew ohw ,naD dna seliM ot ,eiluJ ,retsis sih decudortni dah nitraM neht dnA
.dnoces yna edir ot nrut s’naD eb ot gniog saw tI
”.detacinummocxe tog yeht neht tuB
.dik nellus eht hcni yreve dekool llits eh tub ,kcab tfihs t'ndid luaP ".tey ton tub"
,gnihton eb dluow ytilibisiv
”?flowerew eht saw ohw os ,tiaW“
,worros htiw llud dna ytaews dna derit detsat seliM
,ytilaernu erutainim fo ssolg a gnihtyreve evag ti dna ,rellams dna rettalf kool dray eht edam noom ehT
,ruf ot degnahc ti sa niks ruoy revo elppir ria gnineve dloc eht gnileef rof
.msitpaB ruoy smrofrep dna semoc tnediserP eht sselnu
dees dna ,taews ,niks—
.rebmun siht llac os ,rehtegot efil wen ym gnittup pleh deen d’I dna
,rotcod eht ot og ot droffa t’ndluoc I
.thgin eht otni derats seliM
”.scilohtaC eht fo tuo uoy kcik yeht nehw s’tahT“
,srenroc eht morf sraet yttirg dezeeuqs
.tliub neeb dah ti nehw neeuQ yriaD a neeb ylraelc dah tub
.eciton t’ndid nitraM depoh dna ,desiar erew selkcah s’seliM taht ruf sih ni leef dluoc naD
flesym ekat nac I wonk dna pu ekaw
,tnereffid delleps tub ,stnadnecsed reh fo emos sa eman tsal emas eht dah stnerap yM .lla ta
,newO yb yltrohs denioj ,nitraM dna gerG
,em s’taht fi wonk t’nod I
,deT rof gniod erew yeht tahw fo trap eb ot ecnahc a gnissim tuoba dab tlef eh esuaceb naD
.epoN“ ”?meht ssim uoY“
,daD dna moM"
”.ecnereffid elttil sekam taht tub ,emit eht ta gniod saw I thguoht I tahw t’nsaW“
,thgin lla no yats ton retteb dah pmalteerts eht taht gninialpmoc draeh eb dluoc nayR
noitacav remmus rof deticxe gnieb ekil saw ti tub ,gnileef eht rof drow a evah t’ndid eH
.tsap eht fo ssenredliw hatU eht no dexif llits seye ,deggurhs seliM
,deid deT ecnis detfihs t’ndah eH
,retsnom yna t’nsaw ereht
.sevaw eht dna tesnus eht ot ,dias evraH ”.mih devol I“
,htron kcap sih dewollof naD oS .dias dah seliM
,mottob eht ta dum eht ni
”.esruoc fo ,deT saw tI“
,eurt s’taht fi wonk yllautca t’nod I tub
.gerG dna nayR dna newO ksa em draeh uoy ,ksa em raeh ot ton dedneterp ylno uoy taht wonk t’ndid I fi nevE“
evraH ekil detsat htuom ’seliM dna
.uoraG puoL a eb ot
.rotom eht devver dna ekib sih detrats eH
.aes eht llems dna ,sevaw eht raeh ot elba neeb dah naD tuB
.lewot a naD dessap dna rewohs eht fo tuo deppets newO
.s’kcap eht saw tI
s’taht ,nac I sa drah sa ,em SIH ,em dlo eht gnieb no gniog tsuj
gols a saw noitpo rehto eht
ereht kcab enoemos si
,oot ti teg yeht sseug
.won thgir sniatnuom eht dniheb saw ti yawyna dna ,gninaw saw thginot noom ehT
,dnuorgkcab eht ni erehwemoS
.mih dedausrep uoy tuB“
”.ytiC egnarO dellac saw ecalp tsesolc eht dias gerG knihT .awoI“
”.rehtie yadot t’now uoy ,lleW“
uoY“  "!llew nmad wonk yeht ,dog yb tuB
ylneddus dniheb tfel gnieb saw eh esuaceb ,gnorw tlef ti yhw erus t’nsaw eh taht ,deid deT ecnis detfihs t’ndah eh yas ot emit on dah naD
.detniop enog dah hteet sih was naD
ot tnaw I .eerf eb ot
”,ffo gniwolb tuoba gniklat saw I maets fo dnik eht t’nsaw tahT“
.noitnetta s’enoyreve fo lla dednamed esoht dna setalp repap dna puhctek ycips dna ateevleV fo secils erew erehT ".hguorht
.eb ot gniog saw rewsna sih tahw wonk t’ndid eh yhw derednow dna ,thguoht dna
,hcaeb ynots eht ot kcor fo sevlehs deggaj wef eht nwod deppets yeht ecnO
?emoc ot tnaw enoyna did os ,gnivrats saw enoyreve tub thgindim retfa saw ti haey dna
.ereh erew eh fi ,rof mih knaht d’I tahw s’taht dnA“ ,dias seliM
,newO dna nitraM ediseb pu dellup naD
kraP etatS ssaP sllaF samoT ot ecnartne ehT
.yltnedifnoc ,dias newO
,mih nevig dah deT gnihtemos saw
”?elbuort ni s’eh kniht uoY“ .derepsihw gerG
demialc yltnerappa dna ,tsixe did taht deman namow a tsael ta rO
,dehcnelc tsif siH
”.peels ot gnitteg pleh deen uoy fi wonk em teL“
.detnaw leef em teL
”.flesmih dedausrep eH“
,kecluV erodoehT fO yenruoJ tsaL ehT“ saw sihT
.nagihciM fo tnecsinimer yliree neeb dah notgnihsaW dna
,sehtolc ruoy htiw feirg ffo gnikahs rof
.ot elba eb t’ndluow eh wenk dna reverof gnileef peek ot detnaw eh eno saw ti worros a saw ti fi dna
.pmalteerts a saw ereh pmal eht llac dluoc uoy gniht ylno eht ,etispmac eht fo renroc a saw detanimulli ti gniht ylno eht ,teerts a t’nsaw ereht taht dnim reveN
,em etib ot gniog saw eh fi deksa I“ ”.saw eh tuB
,ereht deyats d’eh dna
,teprac dlo ,repapllaw dlo fo dellems smoor ehT
maets fo dnik hcihw wonk t’ndid eh taht dezilaer eh nehw deliaf sdrow eht tub
,onnud ,em tib reveohw
detfihs dah nitraM dna seliM daetsni dna
.gnivom lla su peek ot tog s’ydobemoS
”.pleh ll’ti fi enim uoy llet ll’I“
.ystna teg ot detrats kcap eht
,detaefednu tub denepmad
,s’seliM ro feirg nwo sih gnileef saw eh fi llet t’ndluoc naD tnemom a saw ereht dna
.noitseuq lacirotehr a saw taht fi erusnu tnemom a rof tas kcap elohw ehT
,dias eH ”.em denrut deT“
.elbissop sa yllacitamard sa flesti laever ot
,puorg eht otni kcab deppets eh sa seliM ta dekool naD ”.deT ot sknahT
.swoc peek t'noD" "?feeb ton yhW"
”.daD ,flesym fo erac ekat nac I“
.hguorht yaw eht lla diputs era peehs tuB
.mih ta pu dekool dna tsehc s’naD morf ecaf sih deirubnu dah seliM
”?tuoba deklat eiluJ
.em nrut ot dereffo eh yhw wonk t’nod I“
,tsrif detrats seibar eht
.sevlehs eht no stun dexim fo snoitceles suoremun-oot-raf eht hguorht tros nitraM dna seliM dehctaw eH
,ti dlot apmarG nehw ,saw larom eht tub
.meht drawot gniklaw ffo tes neht
dniheb morf deniltuo neeb evah dluow eh dlrow tcefrep a nI
,dnabsuH devoleB ,redaeL
,anitnegrA ni nrob saw I“ .dias nitraM
.yaweerf a revo degnoleb ti ekil dekool tI
,htuom sih denepo ,denrut eH
”.pup em sllac eh yhw tuobA“ ,dias naD
.pu mih kcip ot tol eht dessorc yehT
rood nrab ehT ”.haeY“ .no kcab sehtolc sih gnillup ,dias gerG
tnemeganaM ecalupoP namuhartxE fo uaeruB setatS detinU dias taht ngis eht fo wodahs eht ni yats ot
?kramneD morf emac yllautca ew
,evael tpurba sih koot luaP yllanif dna ,esolc ot dehca seye sih llit detiaw naD
”’!tnediserP eht yhw‘ dna ’?anitnegrA yhW‘ ot nwod meht liob annog m’I tub ,snoitseuq ynam os tog ev’I“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,kcab tfihs ot emit saw ti dna
”.reverof retsnom a fo ydob eht edisni renosirp
,dnif ot elba erew syug murof ygolaeneg
.gnikaeps tuohtiw emit gnol a rof rehtohcae ta dekool d’yeht dna ,spets hcrop eht nwod ylwols emoc dah evraH
”.won thgir enola eb ot tnaw t’ndid tsuj I .ydaerla wonk t’ndid lla ew taht ton
.ereh morf ti llems dluoc naD
.deksa neeb d’eh tahw t’nsaw taht taht
,ot em tnaw uoy fi ylno dias eh dna
.deksa seliM ”?yas eh did tahW“
.naD ta derepsihw nayR
”.dne eht ta ereht uoy gnivah thgir leef d’ti dna ,moor tog eW“
.ti derevoc dna ,ti mialc
,yldrawkwa deppirts dah yehT
edis rehto eht gniraen saw yrref eht mih ta gnihgual deppots yeht emit eht yB ”?…spup …pup
,egdol eht ot yaw sih dnif ot elbanu ,sdaor trid nagihciM fo htnirybal a derednaw eH .smaerd sih detaemrep neve dah ti
.nioj thgim I skcap ,teem dluohs I sevlow ,secalp yaw eht fo tuo ,evil ot em rof efas eb d’ti erehw ,ekil ,tuoba nehT
.gab gnipeels s’seliM gnirahs pu dnuow naD
,rednuht eht raeh dluoc eh naht erom yna gniyas erew evraH dna gerG dna seliM tahw raeh t’ndluoc naD
,neht kcab em roF“
.foor eht ni kael a rednu decalp neeb dah taht tekcub a dnuora pu gnippom eeyolpme elgnis eht morf trapa ,ereht seno ylno eht erew yehT
”.nur a rof og dna tuo flow ot emit evah ll’uoY
.siloportem eht hguorht elbissop etuor tsegnol eht ylraen tnaem evah dluow taht dna dnuora yaw eht lla
.yromem sih ni sevlesmeht gnihcte lla
,metsys cidanrot a t’nsaw siht ,on ,woh fo noitanalpxe eht ot denetsil dna
,tew si retaw taht nialpxe ot dah ohw enoemos ekil ,dias nitraM ”,anitnegrA nI“
.nepo gnignah shtuom ,mih ta dekool naD
a htiw ,smoor owt dah yehT ”!?tahW“
,flaheb s’evraH no ebyam ,gnihtemos fo ,luftneser hcuot a eb ot demees seliM
...ot evah lla t’nod eW ?atihciW ot teg ew nehw gniod ew era tahw“
.yllacitamotua t’ndah ti fi
.thgin eht otni seliM dewollof kcap ehT .dias naD
.ereh tog ev'uoy tahw yawa worht t'noD
eb ot desoppus saw efil ym tahw dna saw I tahw dna ohw yawa evag I
,haey taht dediced nayR
:erongi ot elbissopmi saw niar gnimocno fo llems eht emit siht dna ,kcab erew noziroh tsew eht no sduolc eht esuaceb
.sthgildaeh neewteb sdaor ssorca gnikaens
.mih yrd ro mraw ot gnihton od ot devorp retlehs dnuof t’ndah yeht fi eb dluow eh repmad dna redloc hcum woh fo thguoht ehT
.sdik sa rehtohcae wenk eW“
.teg yeht hsittiks woh wonk uoy dna namuh tsuj llits ton er’yeht naem t’nseod taht tub su htiw gnilaed boj rieht eb thgim ti
.denodnaba gnieb tuoba retteb leef ot pu edam d’I gnihtemos tsuj ro
.deddon dna dewollaws naD
,evahs ot dedeen yldab
.htaerb peed a koot newO ”.kO“
…tsuj saw siht dna ,oot esnes ekam esle gnihtyreve edam taht yaw a ni tub
”.ot evah t’nod uoy ,nialpxe ot tnaw t’nod uoy fI“
.etar siht ta loohcs hgih sehsinif eh enigami t'naC
.lavitsef tsevrah gnimocpu s’ytnuoc tnereffid yreve rof sngis dna
.yad lla ylteiuq enod d’eh gniht tsrif eht saw hcihw ,ylteiuq
!seibar YRRAC neve t’nac sevlowereW“ .decniw evraH
,em rof yldab yllaer enog evah dluoc tahT“
”,gnoleb I erehw si hcihW“
,yllufthguoht dewehc dna nub a otni yttap tsal eht dils eteP ”,saw nalp ehT“
,mih rof ylno yrots a eb ot tnaem neeb dah siht taht dias taht kool a naD tohs seliM ”,lleW“ ”?SKROW eno tahT“
.s’nayR dna tsehc sih neewteb detser nru ehT
,eeS .gniht rehto elohw a saw ti yllautca tuB“
.yrd ylbanosaer erew sehtolc rieht dna ,gninialpmoc saw hcamots sih tub ,on dias tsomla naD
.naeco eht ni swap ym kaos ot tnaw I .dnif I gnihtyna eldnah dna
.noisnet eht kaerb ot ni deppets d’eiluJ
.sllordeb eht tuo gniyal saw nitraM dna sekib eht gnirevoc saw nayR ,redluohs sih revO
,egnahc a rof dloh ot naht dleh eb ot erom gnideen
,dias dah naD ”,tahw uoy lleT“
.boj a rof anitnegrA ni saw rehtom htrib yM“
,foor latem detagurroc eht no dednuop dna ti revo tpews niar eht erofeb yrd enob saw tol gnikrap eht taht eciton ot sdnoces eerht tuoba dah naD
.trihs sih htiw rehtob t’ndid ,no kcab snaej sih dah nayR ”?od ew od tahW“
.sdoolf hsalf fo regnad eht fo erawa eb dluohs saera gniyl wol dna sdebkeerc tub
”?knird ot efas gniht fo tros taht sI“
.uoy elpmart ot yrt dna tneloiv nrut ro
fo trap neeb d’I ecnis gnol os neeb d’ti dna
.od elpoep lamron ekiL .efil lamron a evah ot teg dluohs I woh tuoba klat yeht
.enigne gniraor eht dna dniw eht saw raeh ot saw ereht gniht ylno eht dna ,daor eht no kcab saw eh neht dnA
,ti deen uoY .enif s’trofmoC“
nesir dah nus eht erofeb neve dna
,daeh sih fo kcab eht tsniaga detser ecaf s’nayR ”.ko s’ti
.dlot saw I noisrev eht wonk I“
.smrof tuo gnillif detrats uoy ecnis evael t’nac uoy syas elur rehto siht OSLA TUB
,deliaf dna ,lworg ot ton deirt naD ”,ohw
.ni lla meht kcehc ot evraH rof detiaw yeht elihw senigne gnildi fo esion eht revo ,deksa seliM ”?uoy denrut tahW“
.eromyna t’nac eh won mih rof taht od ot sah ydobemos dna
.sdoow eht otni gniraeppasid tsuj snrut koot yeht ,rehtona gnidnif no secnahc ekat naht rehtaR
,saw ereht taht tuo nrut did ti hcihw
”…tuoba yrgna saw I tahw wonk d’I
,eb ot eunitnoc dluow evraH ot gnidrocca dna ,neeb dah daor ehT
,taht dah ohw eno ylno eht saw eh taht derevocsid gerG woh saw hcihW
,rehtegot ffo tilps ew os ,ereht gnithgifni emos ,kcap rehtona ni erew ytraM dna eM“
”?pup ,kcab srehto eht llac uoy t’nod yhW“
dias evah dluow eh sseug ot dah eh fi tuB
.pil nettib a hguorht pley a gnilffum ,tfihs newO tlef eh
,s’seliM saw ti ,s’evraH saw ti ,sih saw tI
.yrd llits ton saw ylbaborp ti
.taht retfa neppah annog saw thguoht I tahw onnud I neht dna
.nru eht no dnah sih tup dna ,edis s’evraH ot pu deppets eH .won
a teg dluoc I fi tub ,hU“
eht ni rettam dne ll’ti nehw gniwonk ll’tahw dna ,dne seod ti llit erehwyna gniog ton er’uoY
.kcen sih fo kcab eht dehctarcs luaP ".era
.nrab eht fo edisni eht dnuora dekool naD
flowerew a otni nrut uoy
htiw emoc dluohs kcap elohw eht cigol taht yb taht deilper dah evraH hcihw oT
.ti ekil ot esoohc dluoc I tub ,flow eht eb d’I rehtehw esoohc t’ndluoc I
.htiw emoc em tel ot uoy ksa annog saw I"
tsuj I ,meht tuoba od dluohs I tahw kniht
”.od llits yeht ,hO“
,detnaw seliM tahw ksa dluoc eh erofeB
.mih tsap dehsup ,sgnaf dna ruf ni ,gerG dna eH
?peels yna teg ot desoppus ydobyna saw woh did ti fi esuaceb
.rewop dah llits noitats sag ehT
”?elbuort hcum uoy evig yehT ?og ti
tiaw ni gniyl neeb dah ti
”.tsrif yas ot sah eh tahw raeh s’tel tsael tA
.ecalperif gib eht fo thgil eht yb
”,rehtie onnud I“ ”!hcum yb toN“
,resolc denael seliM
,ti hguorht dehcnup yeht dna ,draugnav a ,dnabniar niht a ylno eb ot
dna seliM ”.detirehni d’ew nis lanigiro a saw flowerew a gnieb taht
.pot eht revo detaks nus gnittes eht erehw tpecxe neerg elttob eniw saw naeco eht woleB
,kecluV
…adanaC morf ria dloc htiw tcatnoc otni erutsiom eht thguorb maerts tej eht woh ta kool a ekat s’tel ,woN
.dias eh ”.em denrut deT“
,ti fo retteb thguoht
,trihs lennalf a no sdnah reh gniyrd ,rood eht ot emac namow A
.sniatnuom eht otni dna snialp eht fo tuo gnitteg saw ti ebyaM
.rof detacinummocxe nettog ydaerla d’yeht revetahw rof rO .sseug I“
,eciffo rehto siht ta depmats siht teg ot deen uoy ro ,serutangis rehto eseht deen uoy
.od ot tahw dlot eb ot deen t'nseod dna
.ti evig ot teg t’ndid eh rewsna na dah gerG fI
,mih dezeeuqs dna teef sih ot kcab naD dellup newO ,emit a retfA
,sevael yrrebpsar nosmirc gnirehtiw fo lluf stserof
,ti gniyas saw I yhw wonk t’ndid I dna ,did I tahw yas ot gniog saw I desseug evah t’ndluow I .evol saw gniod erew ew tahw wonk t’ndid eW
.yrgnuh lla er’uoy
.elbadnatsrednu saw taht ebyaM .ylikcuL
.denrut neeb dah naD woh gninrom eht ni niaga ksa t’ndid seliM
.esuap drawkwa na derahs lla yeht retfa ,dias seliM
.tneitap eB ,ti ot teg ll’eH
,ereh llits m’I ecnis tub ,haeY“
,niaga sekib rieht detrats yeht dna
”.daor eht no tuo ti erugif ot emit evah ll’uoy ,lleW“
”?boj eht hsinif ot em tnaw uoy t’noD“ .dias naD
.trats ot tuoba tsuj neeb dah ro rehtohcae htiw dehsinif tsuj d’yeht rehtie os
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.nur dnarre ycnegreme na deen uoy esac ni
.boj ycamolpid adnik emos saw ti dias emos
.retaw tlas gninruhc eht otni nwod derats naD .dias seliM
.thgilnoom eulb eht tsniaga dewohs etteuohlis redluohs-hcnuh ynwarcs s’luaP dna
”.ti eveileb I fi onnuD
.em tfel ehs tniop hcihw tA“ .talf dial srae
.detniop dna detpurretni seliM ”.kooL“
tnaw I .hteet nwo ym htiw ti dellik I nehw ekil setsat taem tahw tuo dnif ot tnaw I
”.htneves eht neeb evah tsum I esuaceb
"?wonk t'nod yeht kniht uoY"
,mih ot sevil ruo ewo lla eW“
.detrats uoy taht erom derettaM“
,dias seliM ”,su lleT“
,drah dna tsaf dna duol gnieb
”.ekil s’ti tahw deksa
,gaw ot yrt liat sih leef naD edam taht
.dniheb tfel gnieb ta yssip tog I dna—
,detrats ti woh nialpxe ,erus hO
.seittap nottum dnuorg dekooc eteP elihw
.meht deveileb evah dluow eh ,morf pu nekow tsuj d’eh eramthgin a neeb lla dah ,gniyd s’deT
,floWcaM boR yb
.deunitnoc dna daeh sih koohs eteP
,sgel s’nayR neewteb yal gerG ,renroc etisoppo eht ni revO
,alusnineP reppU eht fo sruoh ehT
”.kcap eht tuoba naht flesym tuoba erom erac t’ndluohs I diaS
”?esle enoyreve gnivol rof enoemos knaht uoy od woh tuB
”!tey ti gnildnah m’I woh wonk t’nod I fi ko s’tI !enif
.em laer eht gnieb ton fo em esucca annog s’enoemos dnoces yna ekiL
flesruoy eb flesruoy gnittel yllanif rof ,enilanerda no knurd skcor eht dnuora rehtohcae gnisahc rof
.eert eht rednu sekib eht deciton eh nehw pu dekrep eH
.ralucitrap ni ydobon ot ,dias d’eh
,kcab emoc‘ dias taht dnuos a ni detpure dna onaclov a ni amgam ekil sgnul sih dellif dna feirg sih fo shtped eht morf pu delbbub tI
.nrut ot elbissopmi eb d’ti dna
,htrof dna kcab deugra d’yehT
.noitsegid flowerew gnittespu fo elbapac saw taht tae ot eganam dluoc flowerew a taht hcum t’nsaw erehT .deirrow ton tub
”?yawyna ,gniksa uoy era yhW“ .seliM dna
,elbatrofmoc erom mih ekam t’ndid noitautis dab a fo tseb eht gnikam rof snalP
,thgin lla no yats ot gniog ylbaborp saw pmalteerts eht
,hcum oot neeb evah dluow ni gninioJ
,llaw eht no sgnah ylimaf ruoy taht euqalp a ekil dna pihsralohcs a teg uoy od yeht fI
.elbuort em nevig dah yeht fi reisae neeb ev’dluow ti ekil leef adnik I“
.era yllaer ew ekiL .kcap a nI
.noitanitsed eht no eye na peek attog s’ydobemoS
’htaM retfA‘ dellac saw ti dias etag nori thguorw eht—
”.draeh ev’I sa raf sa ,s’esle enoyreve sa gnitseretni ro driew sa ton s’tI“
.doog yrev t’nsaw ti fi neve
.flesym rof tuo taht dnif annaw I"
,ijiF ot gnilias dna taob a gnidliub
er’yehT“ .llats rewohs eht fo pot nepo eht tuo dna
",583 otno htron nrut ot tnaw ll'uoY"
,meht hguorht evil rehtie d’I demussa
,noititrap nedoow eht tsniaga kcab gninael
”,thgin tsal noitseuq ruoy derewsna reven ew taht gnirebmemer tsuJ“
”.gniksa er’uoy yhw wonk I“
.saw eh derit woh desseugrednu yllaer evah tsum eH .ypool gnitteG
,mih gnillik erew taht sgniht eht ro ,gnieb rebmemer I nosrep eht ezingocer ylerab I“
.nis a saw I kniht ot evah t’ndid I
,ti teg I ,yeh ,yeH“
.wonk uoy ,meht dellac I“
diarfa saw I tub fo diarfa gnieb htrow saw taht neeb evah dluoc ti thguoht I tahw wonk t’nod I
,daor eht ediseb enilrewop eht no gnittis liat dekrof gnol a htiw drib nworb elttil a erew
,saw taht ohw wonk t’nod uoy fi ohw
.yawa rehtruf secap net doog a detrad dah dna
tsuj dna yawhgih eht ot kcab tog I“ .dias seliM
.dehs rotcart a sa hcum os toN
.reh tuoba hcum rebmemer t’nod I
gniliec krad eht ta gnikool
”!noitseuq eht rewsna neve t’ndid uoy dnA
.leehw driht eht saw I dna ,swodahs s’rehtohcae ekil erew evraH dna deT
"?tuo dnif sklof ruoy nehw sneppah tahW"
.od ot ereh tuo er’ew tahw si deT fo og gnittel ,tegrof t’noD“
elpoep woh s’tahT .uoy rof kool dluohs yeht taht ro uoy rof kool ot erehw swonk ydobon fi ,enola er’uoy fi ,tsol teg uoy fi ,gniod er’uoy tahw wonk uoy fi nevE .snamuh rof ton
.tnecs dna dnuos yb elbawonk ylno
”.mih naht redlo raey a naht ssel er’uoY .haeY“
.laem nwo sih dehsinif gnol gnivah ,seirf s’evraH fo eno
”.wonk ot deen I gnihtemos
",seirots draeh I"
,meht fo neves eht gnoma tilps ot sdeb eerht eb ot tuo denrut ecitcarp ni hcihw
,gabelddas eht ot eteP dewollof seye s'naD
fo draeh reve dah ydobon taht ecalp emos morf sregrubmah fo sgab kcab thguorb evraH
.nosaes gnitnuh rof ylrae oot
,tsehc sih ssorca dessorc smra ,dehcnuh erew sredluohs s’nitraM
.kcab detfihs eh dna deraeppasid ti sa gnilppir ruf tew
,nac reeb a ekil erot dna delpmurc ti llit edis munimula eht ta dewalc dna
.ti did I ,stun saw deT evorp d’taht dohtem a dnuof d’I thguoht I nehw neht dnA
gnignol fo dnik eht htiw
,atosenniM fo ,nisnocsiW fo
.eb ot tnaem d’I naht regnol syad owt tsol ereht tuo neeb d’I
.rehtegot feirg eno ylno ni lla tub
”.enog gnol erew yeht ,no gniog saw tahw aedi yna
,digir ylegnarts ,niht neeb dah daerpsdeb ehT
.evisavrep sa tsuj saw mined dna rehtael tew fo llems eht tub
”.wonk I“ .dias seliM
teg ot elbissop saw ti tsol woh llew yrev wenk eh dna—
.sknalp doow yb decalper saw levarg dna triD
?wonk uoy ,elyts ’flow a otni snrut ohw nosrep‘ a naht emeht flow a htiw hctiw a erom ekil
struH“ ”.struh ti fi nevE
.gnitrofmoc saw hcihw ,eciov sih ni trofmoc oN
.ti gniyas saw eh llit yas ot gniog saw eh tahw nwonk t'ndah eH ".od
,yrettalF epaC dellac ecalp a ta pu dellup dah yehT
,edisni og uoy fi ffo stoob ruoy ekat tub rood neercs nehctik eht hguorht tfel tsrif s’moorhtab ,hcrop eht no elbatrofmoc sevlesmeht ekam ot meht dlot ehS
.keehc ’seliM delzzun dna redluohs s’naD no nihc sih detser eH
.neeb evah dluoc ti sa revo sa ton tub ,ebyam llew ,dias ,revo saw efil ym gnikniht hguorht em deklat eH .emit gnol a deklat eW
d’yehT ”.efil taht evil ot ecalp a em evag tahT
”.dluoc I fi ,niaga ti od d’I
,daD dna moM morf desrepsid I nehw esuac wonk I
.htaerb gniredduhs gnol a werd nayR ”.uoy tog ev’I“
.gniws hcrop eht no tae ot tnew dna etalp eht koot dna trid eht dekcik luaP
,detcartsid saw naD elihw ylbaborp ,ylteiuq ,detfihs d’eH
dias dna seliM ta naD hguorht ecnalg prahs a tohs eH
rehtegot deldduh dna
”.saw taht nehw swonk ohw
,retaw gnitsat-ydnas htiw gnippird llits ,htuom sih ni nam rehto eht ekat ot tlenk naD nehW
”!hemhahe hoohU ?hu auoh haA“ .pley ot hguone desirprus saw eh redluohs sih no deppalc dnah a nehW
”.mih retfa og ew kniht I“
.tey mih devol I wonk t’ndid I“ .dias evraH
,stlep rieht fo ssentfos eht hguorht ,seidob rieht fo taeh gnitrofmoc eht leef dluoc eH
”!revef a dah tsuj I taht srepap laiciffo eht no tup ot wenk DNA
.rehtohcae drawot dehsur llaw duolc dna kcap eht sa deldniwd ,mrots eht hguorht gnidir ro ,gnipmac fo epoh ynA
.yaw eht gnola secalp detalupop ssel eb ll’erehT“
,ti gnirised peek ot derised eh tub
,lleW“ .deddon seliM
,truh dna wol ,gnihtemos delworg dah evraH .dias dah eteP
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.yawa dehsaw neeb dah nru eht rehtehw llet dluoc seye flow neve ton dna
.edisni ytpme regnol oN
gnitirw sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,tnemom a rof desnet naD
,notgnihsaW revo ,ohadI revo ,anatnoM revo ,maerts tej eht fo esruoc eht decart taht worra yerg detamina eht no dexif dah erats s’evraH ?emitnaem
,toofgib gnitnuh ,ymra eht gninioj ,yawa gninnur
,hcum sa tsuj ti dedeen eh taht detsetorp tsomla naD ”.uoy knaht
.teef rieht dnuora selddup gnidaerps eht ssorca derettacs dna mrots eht fo ssenkrad eht no tuo doots rood ssalg eht hguorht thgil hsiwolley ehT
,pukcip eulb ytsur a ni pu dellup dah eteP retal setunim wef A
”…taerg taerg taerg ym ,yldesoppuS“
.serutsap eht drawot
.meht nioj ot evraH rof moor gnikam ,dias seliM ”,haeY“
.detneirosid dna detardyhed saw I“
,dnabsuH devoleB ,redaeL
”.saw eh ohw em dlot eh neht dnA .mih dlot I dnA
.ekib sih ot txen liar draug eht no gnittis seliM dnif ot tuo kcab deppets dah naD
,snoitacav rof etal oot saw tI
.dnim on meht diap dna gnimoc niar llems t’ndid eh tub
.dniheb taes regnessap a dah ekib esohw ,evraH sediseb ,eno ylno eht saw eh esuaceb gerG dna
,rood eht desolc nayR ”…uoy ,haoW“
”?eiluJ dna eteP teg ew dluohS“ .dias naD
,gnihtyna gniod saw eh dias evah dluoc eH .saw I
eseehc gnirts ro stunaep ro ykrej fo sgab dezis-lufdnah dna sag rof gnippots ylno
ssap niatnuom eht erahs ot rehtegot emac yawhgih SU dna daorliar eht erehw gnissorc eht deraelc niart thgierf a sa
”.ot sah ydobemos esuaceb dna ,pup
,htmraw rof ruf rieht ni emos ,sdeb eht no dekan delwarps yehT .eciffo
.mih fo tuo feirg eht gnurw dah mrots eht fo thgin yraew gnol eht ebyaM
levart ni sevlow fo kcap A
,devres neeb d’eh hciwdnas gge deirf dna kaets eht fo suoicipsus saw naD
,eno tfel eht ,gabelddas s’ekib sih tahw ot
tsaeL .derac yeht ekil tlef ev’dluow ti tsaeL
?thgirla neeb evah thgim ylimaf dlo ruoy“ ,derutnev eh ”,oS“
.od uoy ecno ti deen ll'uoy hcum woh wonk t'nod uoY
,ekib rehtona htiw ,esle enoemos eb ot sdeen erehT
.tsixe yllaer did ehs tub ,selat llat tsuj s’taht ,eurt erew sdnegel eht em dlot enoyna taht toN
.riah s’naD hguorht sregnif sih nar seliM
yawhgih yna revo ylbisivni srevoh syawla taht tsud ysaerg wohemos osla tey yttirg eht dna
,notgnihsaW fo alusninep retuo eht fo renroc eht no erehwemos erew yehT
ekirts no erew snoitome sih taht deT rof gniveirg fo derit os nettog tsuj d’eh ebyaM
tuoba ofni yna dnuof reveN
”,onnud I“ ”?yhW“
”,on doG“ ”-eb nac uoy dna
,dias naD ”.nom’C“
.deT saw rebmun taht dnA
.mih dehsuh dna ti no sregnif owt dial newO tub ,thgir lla saw eh fi ksa ot htuom sih denepo naD
rehtegot dedreh meht fo lla peek ot raer eht ta eb yllausu lliw redael eht dna
.thgin ta tsaf levart ot woh dna yad eht ni peels dna edahs dnif ot woh wenk
,yeH“ ”!-htiw melborp a evah uoy fi os
,lagenoD fo silataN dellac tniaS siht s’erehT
”.yrt ot sah ydobemos
.did uoy tahw rettam on trapa llaf annog saw kcap taht neht“
”!keew a og neve t’nac I
.won tesnus tsap tsuj saw ti dna ,esirnus erofeb gnidir neeb dah yehT
,esle gnihtyreve ot eson sih dednilb ti gnorts os saw ti tub ,dab saw ti taht toN
,eciov a derepsihw ”,yeH“
.ti detah llits I tub ,nis ym gnithgif
.detcidartnoc evraH
.ti sdeen ohw eno ylno eht ton er'uoY
.smoor gnikoms-non neeb dah eseht erofeb morf
”,t’ndid ew gnisoppuS“
,tnereffid yllaer
.niaga rehtegot atihciW yb dnuorgpmac eht ni thgin dnoces eht tneps d’yehT .dias dah seliM
,ho ,yas yeht etunim tsal eht ta fi tahW
”.ot sah ohw eno eht m’I won tuB .kcuF“
.pu mih gnivig eb dluow ti gniyas ekil sleef ti
.elbat eht dednuop eH ”!epoN“
,gabelddas s’ekib sih ta bmuht a dekrej dah evraH ?-s’erehW
.pu flesmih gnippiz ,sdoow eht morf degreme nayR
.esir ot gnitrats ydaerla saw ti dias newO
,moor rehtie morf elbakcol htob eb ot desoppus erew taht neewteb ni srood elbuod fo tes
,noissecorp ekilmaerd wols eht ni gnivom fo gnileef eht
.naeco nepo eht drawot tsew gnikirts ot
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.oot ,ereht tog kcap sih fo tser eht erus ekam ot dah eh oS
,erom yas ot gniog saw eh dias evah dluow naD ecaf sih morf dna deppots eH
.tol eht fo dne rehto eht ta yawrood eht no dexif seye ,deksa seliM
,sehtolc rieht mialcer
uoy llac nac I teb I“
.yllug a otni delbmuts I nehw retaw rof etarepsed saw I
"?ekil yllaer saw tahw tahw ksA"
”rehtorB kcaP dna
:eb syawla ll’I ohw s’tahT“ .troppus rof
?elbuort eht fo trap er’yeht fi tahW“
a eb ot gniog saw I tahT
,epyt ’,sdnalmraf eht no sesruc agaY abaB gniod ,lived a htiw laed‘
’enola eb ot tnaw t’nod I ,uoy deen I
won rof tub ,esnopser ni ydob nwo sih ni gnisir taeh eht dna
"!erofeb ti dah t'nevah uoy ekil ton ,nottum tsuj s'tI"
tniop on saw ereht thguoht I
stekcop tekcaj sih ni sdnah sih kcuts seliM ”…tsuJ“
god gib a saw thguoht I tahw dnA
.rewsna ot tnaw t’ndid eh yhw erusnu eno eht llits saw naD dna
,pu saw nus eht erofeb tsomla tsap dehsalf dah ohadI fo revils feirb ehT
,tsal ta meht morf detrap yaw sih ,deT fi dnA
.delwoh dna dray eht fo egde eht ot tnew ehs neht dna
.tey noitanitsed eht ta ton er’eW
,moor siht ni lufrewop ssel saw ruf tew fo llems ehT
.enigne sih detrats seliM
.sekib eht no kcab teg ot emit saw ti dna
.dleh evraH nru eht no dnah eno tup eH
,ytaews ,toh saw eH
,niks sih dedoolf ria looc nehw decniw naD dna ,gniliec eht ta gnirats ,kcab sih otno dellor eH
.tlah a ot diks ot emit ni tsuj gerG otni nur ot tuoba saw eh taht
ekal a morf raf ton ,atihciW fo tsae syaw emos
,retaw eht fo ecafrus eht rednu thgir taht
.daetsni seliM tsniaga repeed kcab dellup
”.dniheb mih evael ot tseb ruo od annog er’ew
.kool dennuts yldlim a erow evraH
,yldrawkwa taorht sih gniraelc ,pu doots evraH ”,erus ,haeY“
.gniksa detterger eH
,anatnoM otni delerrab dna ecar a fo enil hsinif eht ekil gnimoyW fo renroc ynit eht dessorc yehT
.gerG dias ",taht od uoy tel t'naC"  .denihw luaP ".htiw
”,snamuh rof lataf s’tahT“
,rof detacinummocxe tog yeht yhw yas t’nseod yrots eht ,yawynA“
.kcab dekool ecno reven I dna ,ti ni mih dah taht efil a rof egnahcxe ni
.taht od ot em thguat eh tub
.ffo wolb ot detnaw eh
.oot erew sretsis ym htob ,saw moM ,eno saw apmarG esuac ,nis a t’nsaw flowerew a gnieB
.nlocniL dna ahamO neewteb erehwemos renid nwodnur a ni erew yehT
”.taht em sllac eh
,riafnu elttil a saw ti fi neve ,erimda ot daH
”.ti otni gnihsur saw I thguoht eh kniht I“ .nayR yb neht
sueZ …morf cilohtaC gnieb ot detrevnoc dah ohw ylimaf siht ssorca semoc eh dna
.sevlowerew sa gniht hcus on saw ereht evorp ot tuo tes I si tnioP
.nub sih fo sevlah eht neewteb dalas otatop dna selkcip delip nayR
,esir aes eht hctaw ot
.thgil dloc desuffid htiw til erew senilrewop ,sdleif eht ,yawhgih eht
ksa evraH raeh ot emit ni kcab tog naD
,kcap a uoy gnikam rof
.redro fo tuo meht dnuof dna
lacitnamor saw ti deciton I tsrif eht saw taht tub ,rehtohcae no tes dna esor nus eht thguoht dah syawla yeht—rehtegot ylraelc er’yeht ,loohcs hgih ni etaL
si yrots s’yadoT dna
”,od ot pirt siht no er’ew tahw s’taht tuB“
”.tnediserP eht yb dezitpab teg dluoc I erofeb tfel ew tub
”?thgir ,tuo ti dekconk dna ti dniheb pu emac yporhtnacyl eht neht
.neht era lla’y ereh
,pu gnikaw rebmemer ll’I
.etsat eht tuoba erac t’ndid I ,emit eht ta taht tcaf eht htiw ko eb rO
”.hguoht ,gnireffo rof sknahT
”?ylimaf laer ym htiw tuoba yrrow ot hguone tog I t’nevah …tub
,tib a rof og ot su tnaw uoy fI“
,derit demees nitraM
.elbisualp saw taht os ,oiratnO ni pu werg I dnA
?rof gnola emoc lla ew did esle kcuf eht tahw
,rednow ot desu I .onnud I“
”.ees ,onnud I
.mih htiw esle enoemos tsael ta ekat ot dah eh dias dna ,deergasid dah seliM