.mih ecaf ot thgilnoom eht ni doots dna pu flesreh dekcip xof der ehT   .sugam eurt A
.did reven seveiht doog ylurT
?ekil ti si tahW .oot
,roolf eht ot yltneloiv gnulf saw tenniL retsiS erofeb noisnet gnirehtag a saw ereht neht dna
pirg sih ni dexaler ehs sa mra reh tfil ot reh dlot tcnitsni emoS
.detnioppasid m’I“
.tegrat reh yals dna dnif ot tfel thgin eno ylno htiw
.niaga star eb ot evah ot gniog saw tI
”?skaerb yad erofeb ti od nac uoy knihT ?ti od ot hguone
.tsif tnahpmuirt eno ni dleh ssarG fo esreV eht hcihw taorht sih dnuora droc revlis a rof evas ,erab saw oot eH
.erutaerC-flaH tenretnI ruoy
,tsom mih dedeen d’ehs nehw
edisdeb a ot revo gnilaets dna srood rieht fo eno gnikcarc morf peek ot lliw reh htiw deyolla dah retsaM nori fo tib yreve koot tI
.ruf sselwalf eht gnitacidni
.drah gnihtaerb ,dias ehS ”.retsaM“
,klat ot pu tas yllanif tenniL nehW    .saw eh ereht
.esirnus eht dloheb ot swodniw didnelps htiw
!wonk uoy lla rof
doolb detuops ehs sa gnikahs ydob ,gnivaeh stsaerb ,gnillor dna ediw seye
?won yhw ,sraey eseht llA“
.ecneidebo nmelos ni
syad rof ,stnemesab peed eht ni pihsnamsdrows reh gnillirD .doolb s’gip fo telbog a ta gnippis ,sretsis eht htiw dah d’ehs srenniD
”!einniL elttil ,tirips eht s’tahT“
.tius dewollof reh edisni eripmav eht dna
.od dluoc enoyna gnihton saw ereht dna
?evah I lla si siht kniht uoY“
xof eht ,dehsup dna deknay ehs hguoht dna
,lilE dellac si hcihw ,retsaM eht fo drows ehT
,tuo ti tib tenniL dna ,raf oot ylthgils tsirw sih dehcterts eH
,traeh reh hguorht naelc ti mar dluow eh tnemom a nI
eno siht piks esaelp
dednuow ,depsag eH
.gnorts laturb saw baj dna peews yreve dna
.deen taerg fo semit ni tpecxe ,reh ot neddibrof saw nimrev naht erom gnihtynA
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.erehwon morf ezeerb a fo srepsihw eneres htiw reh democlew ,thgilnoom ni deduorhs ,alliv taerg ehT
.krad gniwollaws eht hguorht reh ediug stcnitsni reh tel dna
”…alliv eht tA .thgin rehto eht ,nemow esohT“
,ecneloiv reh fo erusaelp eht ni
tsirw reh no dnuow-etib suoiciv a morf
.sesiri dirolf sih fo gnir eht ni decap taht
,thgilnoom eht ni
.od nac uoy ylno gnihtemos eb ot sah tI
,einniL ,niaga em llik si od ot evah uoy llA .eno s’tahT“
.meht seerf elttil yrev -trA
.dluow eh retsaM dlot d’ehs sa tsuj ,flah ni reh llup ot gniog saw eh dna ,gnuoy saw eh fi neve
,yawa decnad ehs erofeb llew anlu eht wang ot tnemom a ylno gniraps
.regnevacs gnisirpretne rehto emos rof tser eht dedracsid dna
.dessap thgin ylenol fo stnatsni wef A
,dekraps traeh reh ni gniloop doolb dloc ehT   .yawa hserf nrot
,tar reh dehsinif
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.elbaod s’ti ebyam os ,latrommi t’nsi eh dias retsaM
.wohemos mih llik dna sugam eht dnif uoy ,thginoT
daot suomonev a ekil ereh pu gnittauqs neeb d’ohw ,retsnom yrev siht rof gnitnuh fo llirht eht ni deriM
.doG deR eht fo seye eht rof moor ekam ot tuo tuc erew seye reh yad ehT
,eod laicifircas eht ot txen tlenk dna dnob revlis sih deppils ylluS sa gniltsur a saw erehT
,hsurb s’retniap a fo hsals dam eht ekil stnavres sih otno gnarps mih tlaed ehs dnuow hcaE
.enod dah ssarG fo esreV eht gniht eht ezama dna regnuh htiw dleheb xof ehT
uoy reverehw ro ,lleH deR taht ot teg uoy nehW“
,serots doof dna eniw fo slerrab tsap ,esacriats gnidniw a pu yaw reh edam dna rewot eht fo lerrab eht otni yaw reh dnuof ehs nooS   .esohc os eH fi
gnitsaw er’uoy won tuB …“
”.uoy retfa hcruhc gnikcuf
.ytilaer morf dehsirep dah
.flesmih deretsam dah eh nehw ,delrans eh
,yawyna uoy ot nam siht si ohw tsuj
.niar thgil a otni meht evoba wons fo yrrulf a detsiwt ria tnargarf ,mraW  ”.uoy ot
--egatnavda taht tsael ta evah ll’uoy ,latrommi na sA
.won ,thgin eht fo serusaelp eht lla llems dna ees dluoc ehs
:deniamer tcaf eht tub ,noitazilaer eht htiw yrgna saw reh fo trap emoS .elggurts reh gnihctaw ,ereht neeb d’eH .drows siH
.tsaerb tfel reh rednu tsuj ti desserp eh sa ekats taht fo tniop eht ta gniliob raef ciripmav eht tlef
,taorht reh dezeeuqs eH
”eripmaV eht dna nexiV ehT“
.ssik eht otni rettups dna ekohc ot mih gnicrof
.pohsib eht ,ycnellecxE siH fo ecneserp krad ehT
:tfarc sselerutseg eht ,cigam eurt eht ,gnihT emosraeF ehT
,kcirt gnikcuf paehc a saw tI
htuom reh ni yrc sih fo noitarbiv eht gnileef dna gniknird ,mih gnitartenep ,mih gnirutcnup
.ruf dekan reh fo teknalb etihw eht nwod lla sniats nosmirc ,delppot seod eht fo rehtonA .doolb fo yarps eht tsniaga seye reh esolc ot dah tenniL
.elzzum s’retto eht tsniaga htuom sih decrof dna ni denael sugam ehT ”?niats latrom elttil elivres uoy
”.gniod fo maerd neve dluoc dliug elttil ruoy morf esle enoyna naht redraH .einniL ,drah yrev em dekcuf uoY
.noitarepsed htiw dedoolf saw traeh daed reh ylnedduS
.stac laref fo ezag eht rednu ecim laref spart dna
?llew gnitae uoy erA“ .ssarG fo esreV eht dias ”.einniL ,gnineve dooG .tnuc nexiv dellems I thguoht I ,lleW“
,cinap ot nageb ehS
,ytiniffaruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.etalucammi ylkrad saw seidob rieht fo ytuaeb eht dna
?og ylluS did erehw ,yawyna dnA
.thginot slliks eseht eriuqer t’ndluow ehs ,revewoh ,kcul yna htiW
gnilliK .knird ot ydaeR“
”.oot ,ereh ni reh tel uoy
.reh htiw detsugsid eb dluow retsaM
.ssendnik htiw detaert neeb ton dah eH .gnidaelp dna
.welb dniw llihc A
.yaM sa mraw sa eciov laciryl sih ,gats eht dias ”,eloramgir
.srewolf fo nworc sih morf nwod gnitfird erew slateP .dewollaws eH
suoutpmus woh erongi ot deirt dna retto eht ni raef fo ekips prahs eht llems dluoc tenniL retsiS
.wap debbew eno htiw ecaf s’retsaM eht hcuot ot pu gnihcaer saw ylluS
.tuo gninnur yldipar saw ti ksa ot emit eht
,gnihtyna fo uoy dnimer
.nopaew reh fo htgnel eht gnola lla mossolb ot nageb srewolf der thgirb dna ,erom ecno noisnet driew taht tlef tenniL retsiS
eht dnA“ .ebor reh fo eveels eht deppirg tenniL retsiS   ”.niamer wef  ylno nehw sllik lilE .sllarht ynam fi ,sugam llik ot draH
drows reh gnilaecnoc htolc eht kcab gnulf ehS ”.’citereH‘
,ti htiw dellif tsal ta erew seye s’gats ehT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.retniwdim kaelb llits saw ti erehw segde eht dnuora gnuh gof fo niatruc niht a dna ,dnal sih morf dellor taeH
.thgin ytpme eht morf reh ot emoc dah daeD eht fo drowS ,ymenE
.ezeerb eht ni wollib ot nepo gnuh ti taht os
”.yawyna gnimoc ti dah uoY
.pal reh ni rehtet eht dleh dna ti thguac ohw ,seod dekan evlewt eht fo eno ot droc revlis eht dessot dna nwod ylluS dekcik eh ,fooh a htiW .thgiled sih niatnoc ot elbanu ,deirc eh
.serugif erom neetriht thgilnoom yb was ehs dna ,rewot eht revo yllacigrahtel dessap dna mraw denrut dniw ehT
rorret eht yb detrofmoc dna derusaelp ,seye esoht otni derats ehs lliS
,won troffe dna htaerb htiw gnivaeh ydob tcefrep nwo sih
.sreknab gnoma nemiceps tnellecxe na neeb d’eh ,oot suolucitem dna evitnetta ,luferaC
,enots eht ot reh gnihsurc saw ecrof suoedih A
tlef dna ,doolb gnihsiruon ,teews fo htuom a dewollaws xof ehT
.egam-egdeh on ,draziw on saw ssarG fo esreV ehT
.tnemesab eht otni dna htap enaforp eht nwod deklaw
”.lwarb a su evah s’teL !hctib
,hcram ydaets a ni sdleif derevoc-wons eht hguorht dehsup yehT
,dnats ot flesreh dellepmoc tenniL
.denethgit pool eht ,pu droc eht deknay gats ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ekil eb dluow mih gnitib tahw
.dessap dah regnad eht taht won doolb fo llems eht htiw yzzid ,elihw a
.nac uoy fi ,serawanu mih teG .gnivom spots eh litnu mih kcah ,gnihtyreve htiw mih tiH ?ereh
,hcihw fo gnikaeps dnA .gnihtyreve htiw yresim fo hcnip artxe na devol tsuj eH
.evolgxof dna ,calil
,gnilgdelf gnikcuf diputS .diputs
.erofeb nrevat a retne sa hcum os t’ndluoc uoy dna
.ssendekan sih fo emahs eht edih ot
--ereh nam dlo siht ot od ot gniog m’I tahw ekil toN .gniht laer eht toN .dne eht ni ,rewop rof lobmys a ylno saw tI
”,hctib xof yzarc uoY“
.ssergni fo tniop reh gnisoohc ,foor eht no saw ehs ruoh eht nihtiW
.tsal ta mih was dna terrut dnuor taerg eht ssorca dekool gnilgdelf ehT
.eniw noinummoc ekil edaccas gnireviuq yreve gniknird dna
.kcen reh dnuora ssorc eht fo gninrub tniaf eht leef dluoc ehS
.drager krad ,looc sih reh evag dna ,denrut eH
.flesmih esopmoc ot deirt dna ecaf reh otni detnap eh ”…enif …tsuj …s’tahT“
eripmav gnilgdelf eht
,ssarG fo esreV eht fo dnah gninevretni eht yb esle ro ,erutan yb yldnik demrof neeb dah yehT
a s’ti …yllautneve em retfa emoc dluow enoemos wenk I
elohw rieht gnidnes si ssarG fo esreV eht
.swaj reh fo hsang a htiw mih gnitset erofeb rehto eht neht dna edis eno morf noitnetta sih gnikrow ,mih gnisufnoc
ni uoy tel ot eno ylno eht saw eH“
eeht dnammoc I ,droffaR
,thgis tseteews eht
.flesreh revo dil eht tuhs dna
taht seoD ?em erudne t’ndluoc uoy esuaceB ?kaew erew uoy esuaceb dellik reh tog tsuj uoy gnikniht uoy erA“ .sih
-erac ton did tenniL tub
.niffoc reh tuohtiw drah saw tI
wen sti no retsaf dna retsaf nups dlrow eht sa noom eht ta pu gnireep ylneknurd ,dezad dna gnivaeh yal ehS
.niaga em fo tnorf ni tlep ruoy gniwohs ksir ot naht retteb wenk uoy
.epipdniw reh fo warts dehsurc eht hguorht shtaerb gnizeehw ,gnikaeuqs kcus reh edam dna
nroht s’ekirhs ehT
,doots eh ereh won tuB
,sgniws reh fo deeps eht htiw deppans sebor reH .redrah neve desserp xof eht ,noitartsurf reh ni dna ,eno yreve dnuora deppils gats ehT
.reh ta nwod neht dna ,drows eht ta denworf eH
.leehw dna ecnad ot nrut s’tenniL saw ti won dna ,tnatsni na ni niaga rehtegot emac yehT
,yrlewej yvaeh htiw denroda dna sklis neerg-tserof ni dehtaws
.krad lufecaep eht ni delruc ,gnineve eht fo ruoh lanif eht rof rallec eht ni yal ehS
gnihcuorc flesreh ot emac ehS
.taps dna delbbird yretra laidar reh fo nobbir deyalf eht erehw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
tnorf eht morf nepo taorht sih gnillup swalc ,sredluohs sih no
.taorht s’ylluS tuo raet ot ton lliw eht rehtag ot tenniL rof thgin lla koot tI  2 fo
demussa I esuaceb
smoor delbat taerg dna seirellag dna sllah hguorht yaw reh dekcip dna ,eb thgim xof a sa ynnac
.setirW_ijustihoK rednu
ton dluoc ehs llits tub
,thgit depparw droc revlis eht tub ,yrc
.ksa ot deen eht leef ton did ehs ,srehto erew ereht hguoht dna
.gnihton dias eripmav ehT
.noom ylenol eht ot seye s’gats eht morf ezag reh denrut ehs dna
,flesreh koohs ehs neht dna—
hpmuirt lauxes tneloiv eht htiw delgnim taht emahs dna rorroh fo hsulf a tlef tenniL
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
detirem ylno I taht kniht ot gnitlusni s’tI .selcric ym ni egassap fo thgir
.neht yrtemmys eht etaicerppa dluow
.reh gnikahs ,ecaf s’nexiv eht no tips ssarG   ”!emit gnikcuf ym
.llew gnikcuf yreV
.thgin eht otni esor dna pu dehsup ehS
.eod gnipeew eht dna ylluS fo smrof dekan eht ssorca depard gniw krad ,gnol sih was ehs
.derednaw dnim reH
,nettib flesruoy tog uoy dna …hcruhc eht denioj dna tnew uoy neht dnA
.seramthgin reh ni ecneserp sih ekil ton did ehs dna ,noitatuper gnimrala fo rotisiuqni na saw pohsib riehT .rehtie ti tuoba gniyl on saw erehT
.dessap noisnet eht sa ria thgin eht tilps
”?wonk uoy t’ndid ,ylluS hO“
.seramthgin era ,sesreV ecivon neve ,lareneg ni igam tub
,niks retto fo pirts elttil A
,naelc uoy esnelf lliw I“ ,dloc-
,edaced a ni emit tsrif eht rof
”.thgiew tsol ev’uoY
.gnilgdelf sih dna eripmav eht
,tsirw dehcuotnu sih gnippat dna daeh sih gnikahs ,gnihgual saw ssarG
.doog laer tlef taht teb I“
.eriw revlis fo pool eht no mih gnah ot gninetaerht ,ekohc ro
,retirw-semitemos dna flow lacidem a si ohw ,ijustihoK yb
2 traP ,ijustihoK yb ”eripmaV eht dna
,won hteet reh ylno dah ehS
.kcab dereggats ehs sa reh deppord dna
.repsihw a tsomla ni
.sreltna sih ni smossolb gnirewolf erow eh ,remosdnah saw ecaf siH
.dessessop igam eht ylno ecnagorra na saw sihT
.dniw retniw eht htiw ylteiuq dednuos eciov ypsar sih nehw reh rewsna ton dluow eh kniht ot nugeb dah tenniL dna
.llef ti sa wobniar ranul a ni ylfeirb derettilg tI
.wons eht hguorht naelc gnittuc
.ruf fo naf nworb krad a pu gnitfil dna taorht sih otni gnittuc eriw revlis eht
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.nrevat eht ot enog d’eh elbissop yrev saw ti—delbuort ylrevo t’nsaw xof ehT
.ylluS saw htneetriht ehT
thguoht ni yal ehS
.lapo elap dima tes dlareme na :reh erofeb saw ti ereht
.esruoc fo ,won yenom eht deen I taht toN“
***  .ria thgin dloc eht ni yltniaf dekoms ydob sih dnuob taht sniahc dna sessorc eht dna
.mra reh pu dellirht ti fo cigam eht dna wap reh otni deppalc
.naelc sgnaf reh dekcil dna
.llef wolb yreve sa sreksihw reh yb dna spitrae reh revo gnissap htaed dnoces a gnileef
.selzzum rieht detcennoc avilas fo gnirts a ,detrap nem owt eht nehW
.reh edisni yawa gniliob regna fo nordluac eht otni thgirf derrits egasiv gnihcaorcne sih dna
,gninraw a neeb evah dluohs tI .syad dlo eht ekil tsuj ,edisni thgir lwarc ot elba neeb d’ehs ,tihS .tihS
,tem doolb rof deen taht gnivah fo
”--deniatretne saw I tsrif tA
.feiht gnikcuf diputs
.yalp ot tnaw ll’ehs teb I .ylluS
,uoy ot deneppah tahW
.stoc no yltneg gnirons dna srobal s’yad rieht morf detsuahxe
.enips reh pans ot denetaerht ecrof eht dna
.reppus reh rof secalp krad otni dna syawyella nwod reh dewollof sthguoht esehT
.meht no gnitcilfni fo demaerd
gnihtemos od dna pu emoc ot
,srewolf eht dellemS
saw tI .espoc nrehtron eht fo krad eht otni ytic eht fo thgil eht morf dekkert tenniL retsiS ,detaS
”?…neeb uoy evah erehW“
.reh dniheb talf roodpart eht gnikcik ,denotni ehS ”,ssarG fo esreV“
derats ,snordnedodohr gnirewolf sa ylevol dna knip ,seye tnebmal nwo siH
,emoh erew yeht taht won tub
.kcab ti ekat ton dluoc
nevig evah dluow ehs tahW .mih hcuot
,thgilnoom eht ni edis reh no gniyal saw snediam enivrec eht fo eno -llems a fo noitcerid eht ni revo deppans daeh reH  ?doolb s’eoD
,tixe on htiw slennut otni stibbar gnieelf sreets taht raef gnidne-efil gnizalb eht
.dehcram ehs hcihw hguorht tsim telracs eht ni gnikrul htgnerts eramthgin eht rof
reh rof gnitiaw dna
meht llet uoy ,og stsidas tolaez
teem ot ezag s’ylluS decrof ,elzzum s’retto tnelis eht dehcnip eH
.tahwemos reh devorpmi dah htaed dna ,namsdrows tnetepmoc-imes a neeb d’ehs ,eripmav a neeb d’ehs erofeb nevE
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.enots eht ot reh demmals dna sredluohs sih morf reh dekculp lliw taerg a dna ,deirc eh ”!HGUONE“
eripmav dna niht-eldeen saw eciov reh dna ,nexiv eht dias
ni pu dnuob stneconnI .tluciffid …igam
,sevooh erab sih fo peews dna tsurht eht dnuora dnuow ehs oS
,noilednad htiw tnargarf dna elitref dna neerg
.doohnam fo rewolf eht ni kcub yna sa lufhtuoy dna regae ,htaenrednu mih gnilaever ,elttil a sebor sih edisa dellup dniw ehT
.reh revo mool ecneserp krad a tlef ehS
.fooh mrif a htiw sih drawot ecaf s’retto eht gninrut dna srae sih gnitliw ,gats eht diaS
.sreh otni gnihgual
.erot dna taorht sih dnuora depparw hteet s’nexiv eht nehw ylrae pans ti tlef tub niaga noisnet eht rehtag ot kcab gnarps ,kcik reh dekcud sugam ehT  .ylder derepsihw ehS ”.seY“
.ecnelis evitalpmetnoc ni eta dna ,slesrom eciohc wef a dnuof ,srenroc krad eht revo dekcip gnilgdelf ehT
saw noisufnoc dna
.ti dellac retsaM ,nroht s’ekirhs reH
”.tsaf laer snrael ehs teb ll’I
,etag eht ta retsis eht deteerg ,yretsanom eht fo htmraw eht ot yaw rieht edam yehT
.sreltna esoht morf tevlev fo tib a tuc ot tsuj
.neht ,ti saw tahT
delffum a tuo tel dna demriuqs ylluS
.denosirpmi reh peek ot trA sih otni dah eh gnihtyreve gnisucof ,tuo mra ,delrans eH
.doolb s’eod fo lluf htuom
,thgin eht otni sruoh ,yllaniF
raef htiw desufni doolb tneitnes gnivil fo llems eht dna rehto eht no der dna edis eno no nworb saw tI
.tnemeticxe laer gniyarteb eciov dna seye sih ,nrecnoc fo yrekcom a htiw gats eht derepsihW
,hguonE“ .sixa enasni
,llems ot reh rof ria eht ni doolb sih tup ,sregnif sih etib ot tsuJ
,ydob sti morf gnisir terrut hgih elgnis a htiw tnelupo dna dnarg saw etatse ’sugam ehT
.eromyna reh rehtob t’ndluoc dloc eht dna ,noom eht saw ereht tub ,klaw ot dah ehs selim fo rebmun a
,erutsop s’tsileud a
,nroht s’tenniL fo gninevar yrgnuh eht evord gnideelb sih fo llems ehT
tuobA .esreV eht gniteem tuoba ezisatnaf ot nageb ehS
.tnemaciderp s’ylluS ot
,esor nus eht sa peels ot ffo detfird ehs nehw llits gnikniht saw ehS
,rettaf ,gats redlo na sa droffaR derebmemer d’ehS
shtao nrows d’ehS
.eciov sih ni gnixim lla feiler dna feilebsid dna regna ,dehtaerb eh
,spitfooh sih neewteb edalb reh fo pit eht thguac gats eht ,tnemevom fo rulb a nI
,htaerb gniydaets a koot tenniL retsiS ,emac emit eht nehW
.rewot eht ot dedaert ehs ,eid ro llik ot ,seye degnir der htiW
,gats eht diaS ”.taht ekil tsuJ“
.ni ward ot ylnevaeh
.ezeerb gnirps eht ni pmil delgnad ehS
.efil reh fo yromem eht ni debrosba oot neeb d’ehs tub ,gnorw saw gnihtemos reh dlot evah dluohs ti
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.thgilnoom eht ni gninihs tniop denedrah-erif
.stnavres lael fo tuo m’I niaga dna niaga dna
raef saw meht ni dna ,naps eht ssorca seye reh tem retto ehT
,owt eht dleh ylerem eH
”!htaed ruoy detsaw uoy neht dna ,efil ruoy detsaw uoY ?erohw deR uoy
,meht evah ot gninrub saw ehS
.taews tilrats htiw gnirettilg
.mih niard ot evah uoy ebyaM
.llih eht nwod detrats eh sa dias ehS ”.retsaM“
esneffo lanosrep a yrev
,emag ruo ereh einniL hcaet s’teL
.dednetxerevo sugam eht nehT
.ylper eht emaC ”.seY“   ”.ti did I“
erutaerC-flaH tenretnI ruoy ,anueL yb daeR
,emit gnol a ekil tlef tahw ni thgin tsrif eht rof tub
,reh fo ffo delruc gnieb hself reh leef dluoc ehs erofeb noisnet fo spans wef a tlef tenniL dna ,delrans eH
.tser dna thgilnoom eht ni yal ot detnaw ehS
”?meht fo semoceb tahW ?sllarht
.debmilc ehs hcihw ,reddal nedoow trohs a ot yawllah nedoow mid a nwod emac ehS
.evom regnol on dluoc ehs litnu ,dne no syad dna syad dna
.dlrow siht ni detsaw gnihton si erehT“ dias dna
,reh hcuot ot detnaw eh niatrec saw ehS .lataf eb llew dluoc hcuot elgnis A
.nexiv ecin a hcus eb ot desu uoY ?lrig-einniL
.retteb eht ,enod saw siht renoos ehT
”.sseug I ,ffits uoy edam gniyD“
.hctah A .srae kcalb reh fo spit eht gnidlof gnihtemos leef dluoc xof eht nooS
,gnihton morf ti otni gnarps ekats ylloh gnol a dna
,snoitseuq reh ot rewsna ni nettog reve d’ehs tsom eht saw tI
koot ohw dna ,prahs yrev erew
,doolb eht dellems
,won fooh eerf sih deppans eH
.yks kcalb eht tsniaga edalb eht fo enil etihw eht mih wohs ot ti denrut tenniL dna ,ria gnineve eht ni dednuos nroht-s’ekirhs eht fo gnir ehT   ”.enik dlo
.ydaer dna derab sgnaf ,gnitnap
.deid ehs sa reh leef ot
.reh trofmoc ot ylsseltiurf gniyrt
,reh ta kool ot demriuqs eh dna ediw tnew seye s’ylluS
,doolb laer rof etarepsed
,tnemom taht ni tenniL retsiS ot denruter ytiralc fo tib elttil A
.dnah ni drows gnileud delaecnoc elttil reh fo tlih eht koot tenniL ,reh revo llor ezeerb mraw eht tlef ehs tnatsni ehT
.ti hguorht tpels d’ehs tub ,reh ekaw ot deirt eh ebyaM
.gnineppah saw tahw dootsrednu ehs litnu ward ton derad ehs tub ,noitarepsed neddus htiw drows reh fo tlih eht dehctulc wap kcalb reH
.elttil a tsuj fooh sih gnihcnelcnu ,dias eH ”?tahW“
od ot gniog m’I tahw ekil ton
.krad saw dnal eht dna esirnoom saw ti ,ekow ehs nehW
.gnihton dias dna waj reh tes ehS
.rovaf s’retto eht ni etamelats lanretni reh dedne dna denetaerht gninrom eht litnu ,gnippird dna ediw degnih swaj ,detiaw ehS
.detfil selkcah reh sa dne no doots ruf reh fo dnarts yreve ,til seye reh
”.doolb rieht knarD .meht dellik I“
.emalfa sevren daed reh til dna tsaerb reh ni derehtag edirp dam ,niaV
,niaga tnelis saw rehtaf doog ehT
.gnihton saw ereht neht dna
.ekuber laref a dessih dna ,sgnaf reh dewohs
.gnivrats dna lufetarg ,sriats eht nwod tnelis delf gnilgdelf ehT
.ecaf s’retto eht nwod enil a gniward raet-cinap a ffo detcelfer thgilnooM
.ti htiw emac taht regnuh tneloiv eht dna efil-nu wen reh htiw delggurts
!gnirpS fo esreV eht fo elpicsid a m’I
.detatiseh ssarG fo esreV eht dna
,nalp eht s’tahW
.meht gnikaerb fo diarfa saw dna ,revewoh
.sevooh s’esreV eht fo hcuot eht rednu deppid gnilgdelf ehT
.yretsanom rieht gnikoolrevo llih eht ot tsal ta emac yeht ,dloc eht yb derehtobnU
.egar dnilb-flah htiw gats eht no nwod gniraeb ,hsalf yleets a ni mih no saw ehS
esol ot gniog saw tenniL retsiS
sgnaf esohw tub ,eripmav ron xof rehtien saw taht tenniL retsiS ni derrits gnihtemos ,siht gnieeS
,koorc latem llams a htiw wodniw a nepo desaet
.dnammoc s’rehtaF saw tI“
pu tis ot ylluS gnicrof
”?dab leef uoy od ,hO“
,stlep etalucammi rieht gniniur
ereht ti gnidloh mih ees ot pu decnalg ehS
.noitnetta lluf ta doots eh woN
.stlob wobssorc elbisivni fo egassap eht yb trapa deknay dna tilps
.ti od nac uoy skniht retsaM .erehwemos kaew s’eH .evivrus ot ti did uoy fi uoy evigrof dluow retsaM
keirhs suoedih a dna ,kcab s’retto eht pu pitfooh a dils sugam enivrec eht ,tsirw sih fo kcilf a htiW
.dnammoc igam eht ylno hcihw ,trA hgiH
devom taorht reH
.rehtet ’sugam eht fo eerf ekorb ehs sa eod gniniamer eno eht fo gnibbos dekcinap ,citnarf neddus eht raeh dluoc ehS .yltfos gnivaeh
.terrut eht fo retnec eht otni reh gnidael ,kcab decnad dna nups ,owt ro tsurht a fo tuo derehtils eH
.tlih eht koot dna
”!tcesni gnikcuskcoc uoY !aelf gnikcuf uoy
.rewot eht revo lla slatep derettacs dna yb ylizal welb dniw gnirps fo ffup A
.taorht reh gnihsurc sregnif deppit-fooh ,noom eht ot pu reh dleh dna enots eht morf reh dekculp eH
egalliv elohw taht
”.ebyam ,dlrow eht ot niaga emoC
.sredips tnafni fo teprac a ekil niaga reh revo tperc seiromem dna ,deunitnoc smaerd ehT
.reh no gnikrow saw ti dna
snoihsuc no tlenk yeht sa llits dna dekan hcae ,nemow eod gnuoy erew meht fo evlewT
.enots eht no gnikcilc sevooh ,delbmuts ,deleer ssarG fo esreV ehT   .keirhs rehtonA
flesreh desopmoc nexiv ehT
?drows reh saw erehW ?nroht nmad eht saw erehW .yldliw deporg swap reH
.noisnet gnirehtag emos tlef tenniL retsiS
.kcub reidlos duorp a sa ehtil dna niht
.dednuow dna rednet ,roolf eht no ria fo sllup deggar deplug ylluS dna yltnelis dehctaw seod fo elcricimes eht ,meht dnuorA
.gnihtemos ro taog laref a rof luos reh fo tfel saw tahw dlos evah dluow ehs hguoht dna ,oot yrgnuh saw ehS
.seye reh desolc tenniL
nexiV ehT“   yojne esaelP
,gninihs dna tew dewolf smaerts erehw syellav ynit otni nwod ,sllih elttil dna segdir wons revo dehcram nexiv elttil ehT
tenniL ,emit tsaL
,seye sih ni noisufnoc saw ereht tsriF
,doG fo eman eht nI“
eeht eman I ,noitisiuqnI yloH s’ytsejaM siH fo stnavreS lufhtiaF dna dooG eht ni detsev rewop eht htiw dna ,eeS yloH eht fo eerced yB“
tsol saw ehs –won ti dnif ton dluoc tenniL tub ,reh ni
.ti fo enihs etihw eht gnirimda ,tigid-fooh eno ni eriw fo htgnel a dekorts eH ”?he
.deef ot egru reh rof neve ,pu teg t’ndluoc ehs won dna ,reh fo tuo gnihtyreve nekat dah thgif ehT
,rewot eht fo enots eht no yal tenniL
.dnim reh ni hguorht melborp eht gnikrow ,setunim ytriht tsomla rof ssarg eht no ti delcric ehS
.rednuht ekil gnar eciov s’gats eht nehw
.niaga derumrum ehS
dekcut yletarepsed saw liat sih dna rewot eht fo enots eht nopu delruc saw emarf yraew ,dlo siH
.sgnaf etihw dna spil kcalb s’nexiv eht ssorca flesti gniraems hajulellah der krad a
.smaerd yb delbuortnu yllatot saw ehs
.noitcurtsed reh rof yrassecen saw esle revetahw od dluoc eh neht dna
,anueL yb uoy rof daer ,ijustihoK yb ”eripmaV eht dna nexiV ehT“
,emitgnirps saw ti enola ereh dna ereh tuB .reknab erem a rof tneiciffus neeb evah dluow siht dna
.meht fo eno fo llif lufdaerd reh evah dluoc ehs erehw
,ytic eht ni dneirf ylno reh fo deb eht revo gnidnats reh tfel eW
seye sih otni gniknilbnu gnirats ,weiv otni emac ti sa gats eht fo ecaf dliw eht dehctaw ehs os
,’krow rof etarepsed yrev eb tsum ehs ,ho‘ thguoht I ,thgin tsal nwot ni dnuora gnikluks uoy was tsrif I nehW“
,alliv s’droffaR morf erutraped rieht edam d’yeht ecnis lobmys yloh a ekil reh gninrub neeb dah noitseuq ehT
,kcab spil reh werd tenniL dna drawrof deppets eH
”?naem I ,eripmav a gnieB
,ecneitap rotaderp htiw moolg eht hguorht delwarc ehs sa thguat dellup efil dlo reh fo daerht emoS
,srettat ot nrot dna dehsals ebor ,reh ot revo deklats gats ehT
.ezeerb gnirps tnasaelp eht ni saw ti
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.nam dlo gnipeew eht fo mrof delpmurc eht fo kniht ot flesti trevid thguoht driht yreve gnivah fo daetsni
traeh krad reh amuart eht ro reh fo erawanu yllatot meht fo lla ,sdiam dna stnavres gnipeels fo ytilibarenluv eht esnes dluoc ehs reh dnuora lla dna ,seye rieht htiw reh dewollof semarf dedlig ni stiartrop hsivaL
.rewolf ni neerg saw lla dna ,tpels stnavres eht tperc ehs elihw dnA
taht lla dewollaws d’uoy kniht yllaer t’ndid I tub ,seye ruoy ees dluoc I ,einniL hO“   ”.eid ot
”?won em ot kcab emoc yhW
,ebor sih fo tleb eht tuc ot saw deveihca d’ehs llA
.flesreh ni egnahc eht ta delevram dna swodahs eht dima devom gnilgdelf ehT
.derrucco thguoht a nehT
.ekal a ssorca kcor a ekil enots eht ssorca deppiks
’rehtaF‘-xe ruoy erus m’I“
”,niaga taht od uoy fI“
evah dluoc I ,dnasuoht net ,srekat-dnuow eseht fo dnasuoht a evah dluoc I
.pitfooh a htiw yawa ti werd ssarG fo esreV ehT
.ylpmis dias eH ”.ydaer erew uoY“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.lanoitnetninu fi ,tca yloH …niap
’srehto no gnikaT“
.enobralloc s’gats eht tsap gnaf repiv a ekil ti evord dna tnatsni na ni ti nups ehS
.nwod yltew delgnad ,gnirts a sa niht
”.einniL ,em no nwod kool yllaer tsum tluc repeeW elttil ruoY .uoy
kcab meht ekat dluoc eH dna seye nwo siH hguorht was doG
,detnaw uoy tahw taht sI .sevil rieht detsaw ev’uoY .oot ,emit ruoy detsaw ev’uoY“
,krad eht ni gnideelb deyaws ehS
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.senob yhtlaeh ,gnuoy rieht gnirettahs dna seidob emoselohw rieht ta gniraet
.eenk eht ta gel sih deppans dna tuo dekcik retsis eht sa detnurg neht ,sehcnup dliw wef a thguac ssarG
,edisni uoy del eh sa ereh thgir morf dehctaw I .thgin tsal
.yleneres edalb eht gnitalpmetnoc
gnol tsal ll’uoy knihT
tsal ta niffoc reh otni kcab deromalc ehs sa sgniht ynam fo thguoht tenniL retsiS
,droc eht detfil eh sa elims ynnus a reh evag eH
.gats eht dias ”,namsdrows a erew uoy thguoht I .einniL hO“
deR uoy ,ereh emoC“
htaerb reh yawa dehcnerw tI
,pots niap eht ekam emoc ot reh rof gnimaercs erew uoy nehw ,oga tib elttil a tsuj dnA .thgin tsal esuoh ruoy otni reh tel uoY“
,doolb latrom fo lufhtuom tsrif reh retfa dnim reh
.gnittilps saw noitnetta s’tenniL
,noitaerc lla rof esiarp htiw hserf selzzum niwt rieht ,gof-doolb eht hguorht rehtegot ylneknurd delbmuts yehT
,igam eht fo eno saw eH
ytip eb ot desoppus saw erehT
drah gnihtemoS   ”.niap neve toN
.stoob reh tub dnuos on saw erehT
”.sruoy fo tuc dna nrut elttil yreve was I tub ,peelsa-flah dna knurd saw I thguoht uoY ?rebmemer ,ecno em fo tnorf ni leud a thguof neve uoY“
,nemtoof gnipeels fo rebmun a tsap
.tnelis llef ehs dna ,kool a htiw ffo reh tuc eh tuB ”—nni llik oT“
.ytpme saw esuoh eht tuo mih thguos ehs nehw tub ,ekawa llits saw spahrep ylluS fi ees ot esor ehS
.sretsnom latrommi hcus lla fo straeh eht ot evitan si taht nmyh gnillik tneicna taht gnignis
.efil sih fo riaffa yreve ni suorednop dna emosrebmuc
,pirts gnol a fooh sih fo pit eht morF