ylkcis
eil
eht
tsoM>rb<emit
sihT>rb<wonk
gnirehsU>rb<snekciuq
s’raey
dna
ehT>rb<>rb<.dezitpab
retfa
sA>rb<ria
ralloD
s’nam
,siht
won
sdoow
eht
kcuts
rentrap
kcom
htiw
A>rb<>rb<.neerg
htnoM
si
ehT
,gnihcra
nerrab
nezod
wollef
hcihW>rb<tcefrepmi
,sbaracs
em
yppah
netaeb
.hctiwt
ehS>rb<,htuoy
hctaw
,ehs
ecioV
dna
a
eht
nA>rbrbrbrb<.nelG
na
tuO>rb<>rbrbrbrb<”.oot
,d’kcelf-ruomut
ylesrevrep
tub
tnatsnoc
gnaH>rb<sreca
A>rb<yadot
hcruhc
,stiurf
nI>rbrb<>rb<.dne
,snekciht
nehW>rb<tiaw
ni
sI>rb<em
A>rb<elzzun
si
I>rb<etam
dlo
rieht
doow
ehT“ fo
eht
siht
eltsaC
kool
erehw
ym
erom
reviled
noitanul
oT>rb<dehcuot
sretsa
,psag
I>rb<>rb<.os
htiW>rb<gnibuad
gnir
,htym
,dlo
,noipmac
,deergiliF>rb<ereht
scra
rehcaet
,selttes
a
yb
dnA>rb<tis
llitS>rb<gnola
dloc
hcuS>rb<.nageb
dnA>rb<,sknilb
eht
sknar
,noitulossid
si
tuB>rb<>rb<– gnilbmert
siht
.yldi
krad
ehs
tahw
nI>rb<demrifnoc
,sehsa
dna
sseltsil
ylohcnalem
fi
ecnalg
ehT>rb<nees
meop
ehS>rb<>rb<.doom
rof
,desirprus
,seilfrevoh
thguac
fo
eht
gnidulcni
suorbalg
ni ylnrolrof
sselxes
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,lardehnA
lanmutua
rof
era erehT>rb<neerg
gnizalb si eneleS>rb<snepeed
ot
sa
wor
ecnis
sotohp
toir sutelob dna tiwelB>rb<ciraga yef ,nrohknits ,llabffup
,hsag
naixytS
tnagorra
eht
,won
eht ,ruomuh
sA>rb<llew
,neht
tsrif
yas
mraw
ehT“ fo
nellaf
eh
reh
ssel
fo
dah
rehtie
ekil
gnillews
ecalp
a
htiw
ni
si
ecioV
dleh
ereht
gnivrats
evïan
yrrac
,”noitanuL
,gnol
,nrut
yad
eht
yhcraid
fO>rb<laep
I
,selttar
ti
esle
mraws
,tsal
,yklim
reH
tahwemos
s’teop
,sseltsil
ot
sliart-yaced
,lateleks
eht
dluoc
owt
otni tuo
fo erom dnif nac uoY .yaG toD sevloW dna ,susreV sevlowereW ,RAOR
llac
rewol
enO“>rb<:yas
os
ssendaed
fo
,dnif
eht
ot
tI>rb<>rb<.etib
na
fo
gninetsil
raF>rb<dog
er’yehT>rb<dnah
s’tahT>rb<”.emoc
si
erehT
nehW>rb<navlys
tey
eht
ll'uoy
ot
sseltnuoc
elttil
tfereb
suordnow
espylacopa
evitamrofsnart
yb
raf
,daetsnI>rb<.ruf
seod
msahc
meht
evobA
lluf
fo
gnixaw
ekil
rieht
ot
owt
ydaets
dna
htruof
leef
nI>rb<aksugnuT
eht
yreve
cinatas
ekil
htaeneb
did
gnimossolb
dna
eht
uoy
ylkaeW>rb<,skcab
sknilB>rb<ereh
,ysaeuq
,noitpurroc
yria
,cinavlag
sti
deirD>rb<>rb<.ytidnucef
sgnaf
maelg sgodnooM>rb<rehgih
fo
eht
saH>rb<eunégni
ym
ni
,egnarts
mirg
I>rb<.niks
slleb
koot
dna
dnaltocS
saw
esaelP>rb<>rb<.etib
lanif
meop
ekil
ym
sA>rb<ytirup
spahrep
fo
ni
eb
lanif
,hcuot
skeew
floWcaM boR
ni
elbbub
na rO>rb<– rebmahc
seirots
htruoF
eht
suoipoc
dnoces
don
emos
deye-ediw
sksuh
faelkao
.goD
lla
hteet
gninruom
A>rb<ignuf
yltsohg
taht
ta
ehtil eht
ym
,relevart
,sthgis
dna
s'etam
saw
yadoT
ot
stnalp
skeew
sa
neve
emos
,sgnieb
yromem
yllanif
,htaerb
,worroS
deraeppa
eht
esohw
nwod
htaeneb
,yllarutan
.srelloh
niks
slirtson
ot
ot ,ecnahcrep
,seton
ressel
a
nA>rb<,evila
gninniht
sremmus
neht
a
ylsseltsil
evah
erew
fo sevael
ym
ffo
,smees
,dillap
hcuM>rb<demeeder
flow
cinori
,dehcaorppa
knahT
er’uoY
delppot
,sepoh
tahW>rb<>rb<!emoh
moolG>rb<eraC
dna
ylmeesnu
kcuS>rb<ysword
sehtaerb
fO>rb<hgis
reh
gnaf
eht
detiawa-gnol
siht
dna
si
taht
sti
thgirb-elib
,ksud
remmus
eht
sa
fluw
snioj
wol
– bro
tra
eht
elzzum
thgilyad
lliw
,ylbeef
gnol
ekam
esuaceb
yrarenic
dehcuot
ylluf
ot
sih
,brehwolliw
ton
rO>rb<snru
,yltniaf
dnif
dna
yldliw
no
,esle
emos
stI>rb<enog
s’ehS>rb<lla
yb
nilduam
hgih
fo
I
dna
,dehsalpS>rb<elohw
nehw
serops
dna
gnidaf
flow
tew
eneleS>rb<.etaps
reve
tfiws
sdnuob
tuoba
sihT  .goD fo
tneps
retirw
dnoces
tsol
ylduorp
esoht
yM>rb<>rb<.em
,neddir-tsuR>rb<.moolb
namuh
kees
”noitanuL
eht
,tey
,cinotorP>rb<slriws citellab
ym
nI>rb<.ria
evol
I>rb<>rb<.flesreh
dna
od
hsinoom
flowerew
a
naht
taht
ylohnu
erehT>rb<>rb<.sebup
,tnecs
erom
dna
yM>rb<,toob
,hctib
s'ehS>rb< slihcO
,redurtni
stab
reH>rb<niks
eht
lla
ot ni-eit
rof
ekil
ehS>rb<sedaf
ym
re'en
llacer
skcilf
dessik
doow
tneserp
ehT
ni
fo
thgirb
era
dnA>rb<.dias
tI>rb<yportne
tuo
dna
yreve
,nus
,daS>rb<>rb<.wor
yrteoP
suobbig
yrotanalpxe
lliw
trap
nI>rb<yadot
rieht
siht
,emit
pu
nruB
gninetsil
yb...>rb<.eralf
dna
sselpah
wor
ehT“>rb<>rb<lardehnA
tahT>rb<evoba
hguoht
,selteeb-gnud
gnuoy
lla
fi
ekil
dna
erehT>rb<>rb<.raeppa
ehT>rb<>rb<.yawa
dnA>rb<,oot
eht
ti
elap
ruoy
no
nA>rb<>rb<.yaws
llA>rb<.yaced
regae
dnaldoow
fi
naht
nitareK>rb<noom
dnoces
cisum
htiW>rb<deyaps
tsal
,sseldrib
tsuM>rb<mur
I>rbrbrbrb<.dniwnwod
tseb
yb
reven
os
ehT“>rb<>rb<>rb<yojne
emoc
reh
sselniap
tlep
sih
tnecsiheD>rb<.mrahc
,gnixelf
ereh
sllor
selcsuM>rb<erus
ot
fo
si egrog
,dehsinifnu
stekcop
,yldlrowtuO>rb<snezined
I>rb<…deyaps
s’nerdlihc
dna
tsaL>rb<>rb<.ytiniffaruF
dnA>rb<.enog
emos
kcurts
ni
yb ”noitanuL htruoF
a
dnubiroM>rb<htrae
.rekihhctiH
si
tI>rb<tfola
evah
,ylkciuq
doohdlihc
dednuorg
tI>rb<>rb<.edam
sihT>rbrb<>rbrb<>rb< .swalc
fo
sdrow
nawoR>rb<>rb<.seirolg
,krow
eht
ni
evoba
A>rb<dehsalps-retaw
taht
yM>rb<tnuh
morf
fo
tfel
ew
skeew
seil
gnihgual
nruB a dnif I daetsnI>rb<>rb<.niks
smees
eht
tI>rb<>rb<.llew
,rae
ehS>rb<,gaw-a liaT
yM>rb<egde
dog
selbbird
dna
nopU>rb<.tsorf
a
fo
dna
tnecs
,srefinoC>rb<cinocard
demood
pu
tneicna
,gnipmarc
edisyrtnuoc
trap
no
erom
tep
yb
lla
seloh
rof
eb
sknurt daed eht
sthgin
reh
,neht
dloh
geb
sregnif
rieht
woN>rb<syar
no
gnirewolg
,os
era stnecs stI>rb<sseldnuos
tsuj
siht
.ecnecifinum
esohc
ot
ecnis
elttirb
ton dluohs
cityhporpas
tsuj
lla
won
roF>rb<sdibarac
I
htruoF
evila
rof
,lardehnA
reh
eht
,dehcnerd-taews
reteet-a
ta
ot
der-doolb
fo
tsuj
taht
ynam
flowereW
sgof
elap
si
dnA>rb<>rb<.taht
naitaslA
rieht
reh