.evom dab a ylbaborp saw sfeirb ym ni ereh gnittis taht si wonk did I tahW
.thguoht d’I naht rekciuq ereh erew yeht ,yaw rieht no eb ot gniog erew yeht dias enohp eht no eciov eht nehW
.erugif ym ta nwod dekool dna teef ym ot dereggats I
.enim ta kcab dekool eh dna
.ereh ni ydaerla gnihtemos yletinifed s’ereht ,yvaeh s’tI .eldnah eht yb gab eht pu kcip I
”.knird ot doom eht ni ton m’I“
.sgniraeb ym teg ot deirt dna dnif dluoc I lla derehtag I
?kcerwpihs yM .kcerwpihs A
.nalp-ffo dna etarepsed saw eh esuac‘ ti thguob eH
”?uoy taht si kciR ?kciR“ ”?olleH“
.gnidliub eht fo tuo gninnur dna nwod enohp eht gnittup
.xofnogard reppad
.desiar worbeye ,ylper I ”?ti si ,hO“
.etteragic a gnithgil
.efil ym ni erofeb mih nees reveN
,tsenoh eb ll’I …I“
wohs VT taht tuoba gnihtemos gninoitnem
dna kcab deppets eH
d’eh fI“ ”.deneppah tahw fo erawa ereht er’uoy fi krow t’nseod ti rof em gnimalB
.ma I reveohw ,esac siht ni ,rO
.draoba em serutseg eh dna ,noitatiC ansseC a sdrawot em sdael etoyoc ehT
”.og s’tel ,thgirlA“
tropssap ym elots eh ,oS“
,pu sdda lla tahT“
!kcawhT ”?won ti sI ?ti sI“
”?kroY weN ni nwod hcuot ew ecno nalp eht s’tahW“ .nageb I ”,oS“
,ylhtooms mra s’knarF .deplug I
.dluoc I seceip dna stib dna sesactius tahw gnibbarg ,htrof delbmarcs I
.yromem ym deggoj taht gnihton llitS
.enalp eht fo wor kcab eht ni tis I
.thgir sih no doots knarF dna ,tfel ym ot etoyoc ehT
.derepsihw I ”.ton ro seiromem
.worrob nac uoy enohp a tog ev’I ,ecallaW .rM erus ,haey ,haey hO“
.hpargotohp a dnuof I ,stekcop tekcaj tius yaw-eht-fo-tuo erom eht fo eno nI
.derepsihw eH ”27‘ ecnis
,denialpxe flow ehT ”.ssenisub saw ti taht tsuJ .yhw liated hcum oot ni em dlot t’ndah uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.riahc a no mih ,deb eht fo egde eht no em
.worb ym deworruf I
.gnar enohp eht ,ylnedduS
,ruf kcalb htiw flow a ylgnimees ,eninac rehtona ot txen doots ,em dah tI
.dias eH ”.siht revo gals gniworht srepap erom yna tnaw t’nod I dna 4 ta enohp eht no reywal a tog I ,yadot deid ylraen uoy hguone dab s’ti
.spahrep ruomuh swollaG .elkcuhc I
.seulc yna em evag yeht taht ton
,yltnatcepxe drawrof denael flow ehT
.roolf eht ot delpmurc dna eehsnab a ekil demaercs kcaJ .tohsnuG .noitom
elpmet s’drazil eht ta erauqs gnimia ,deilper hateehc ehT ”.t’nod stelluB
.eno ot 3 tsael ta dennugtuo saw I woN
.rehtaew lacol gnissucsid retneserp a dna
.dias I ”.uoy eveileb I .thgirlA“
,deireuq I ”?enalp etavirp A“
.og eno ni htob su llik nac eh serugiF
”.ti teg yletelpmoc t’nod llits I esuaceB“
.keew tsal morf yrots a ot etadpu nA“
.daeh ym rof nug sih desiar eH
.ssalg ym nwod gnittup ,deksa I ”?deneppah htrae no tahw em llet enoemos nac …os ,thgirlA“
.kcab nrut neht ,swor taes eht fo eno dniheb ni esac eht edils dna pmar eht otno pu spets wef a ekat I ”.ton epoh od I
,denialpxe hateehc ehT
.dias I ”.em htiw erew uoy rehtar d’I“
.deilper I ”.dnuorga em nur ot deirt t’ndah uoy fi rebmemer d’I ebyaM
.ereh dnuora gnignah noitamrofni emos eb d’ereht spahreP
.nirg a htiw dias I
,cisum etorw emit a nopu ecno dna scimoc torraC niatpaC gnitcelloc
.ecnuob seuqehC“ .ykahs saw eh
,retto na ,namow A
”?ycnegreme ruoy s’tahw ,119“
.sseldrager swen dab si tropssap sih gnivah tuB“
.niaga tropssap s’knarF tuo dellup dna stekcop ym dekcehc I
,kcerw taob eht ta won regdab eht ees dluoc I .enecs eht dennacs I
.deilper I ”.thgirW knarF“
”.smret fo sdnik esoht no ton
,deredro eH ”.tuo ,uoy ,thgirlA“ .ni
.em ta redro rehtona dekrab tsuj uoy
”.stroper VT eht nees ev’I
.nwot otni reggats ot detrats dna
.xof der a dewohs noitcelfer ehT
.yrreP ot ti gnidnah ,dias I ”.kcerw taob eht morf siht derevocer I“
.tnelis yrev tnew dne rehto eht no eciov ehT
.knabrevir a no flesym dnif ot ekowa I
,rab a morf deppandik saw eh taht detcepsus si tI
;noitcafsitas detnaw eH
?saw I ohw wenk eH
…esuaceb …ylcilbup meht erow reven …eW“
.niaga pu doots dna gab eht pu deppiz I ,gninnirG
.ti fo ffo snalp drawno yna gnisab erofeb kcehc ot gniht suoivbo na ekil demees ti
”.ylsuoires em ekat ot deliaf syawla uoY
”?uoy od ,yad yreve deppandik teg t’nod uoy …naem I ,haeY“
.lufwa ylrettu eb ot dekooL
,sdon dna sgurhs neht ,esuap sekat etoyoc ehT
.saw eh reveohW .ecallaW kciR saw I demees tI
em dnuora smra sih depparw eh sa pu dda ot gniliaf deunitnoc yehT
meti na …neeb ev’eW
.ti revo gnikool ,tropssap s’knarF pu dekcip dna enizagam eht nwod werht I
.enisuomil a otni deksihw saw I ,tcejbo dluoc I erofeB
.ylwols dil eht piznu dna esac eht ot kcab hcaer I
.tropssap ym dna esnecil s’revird ruoy ,ydob ruoy dnif yehT
.roolf eht no dloc tuo
.deddon tub delzzup dekool eH
.knabrevir a no pu dehsaw I“
tog s’tI .gnir deruoloc-revlis llams a dnuof I ,siht sa llew sA
dah demees ti ohw yug ylno eht
,dekrims hateehc ehT ”.eceip eno ni lla er’ew tsael ta ,yeh
.dedivorp neeb dah taht tius ycnaf yrev rehtona
.dedda yrreP ”.dnim ni dah ew tahw t’nsaw ,tsenoh eb ot
dluoc I ,nwod taS
.dias eH ”!uoy dnuof yeht dalg os m’I ,kciR hO“
.daeh ym ni enod dah ti sa yltcaxe gnidnuos ton eciov ym ,dias I ”.em esucxE“ .regdab a
.hctam ot demees yehT
.esnecil s’revird a was I ,tellaw a eb ot dnuof I tahw tuo gnilluP
.dnim ni dah I tahw rof gib oot raf dna ,htolC
,enalp taht ni efil ym devas uoY“ .deddon I
.ti rof raf os emoc d’eh
.ti did I ekil kool d’ti os ,no deppandik saw kciR taob eht ni ti detnalp uoY
.srotagitsevni eht dna em neewteb gnitteg detrats dna
.hpargotohp eht morf flow kcalb eht deretne rood eht hguorhT
.detsetorp I ”.elpoep eseht pleh ot gniyrt m’I ,nam yeH“
”~ot erusaelp ym eb d’tI“
.noissimda fo ecirp eht htrow era sgniht semitemos tub ,thguac teg yam I“
.tuoba gniklat tpek elpoep taht ’hctiP giB ehT‘
.yfmoc saw taes ehT
.nageb eH ”.detacilpmoc elttil a s’tahT“ .dehgis etoyoc ehT
…er’eW .yltcaxe toN“
.deksa eH ”.pu degnab ytterp eb tsum uoY
.pal ym ni thgir nug gnikoms eht dah I ekil demeeS
”thgirW knarF fo etaF ehT“ si
.ti ni dekool dna retaw eht ot dereggats I .lla ta gnihtoN
,gnorw tlef gnihtemoS
denraw eH ”.terger ll’uoy ekatsim a ekam t’noD“
.krims a mih evag
.yaw sti no omil a tog I“
,seohs ym dna skcos ym naht rehto ,lla tuoba erew esoht ecnis ,sfeirb ym ni deb eht no tas I
;tey em toohs ot gniog t’nsaw eh wenk I
.yregrof a saw ti fi ees dna yrt ot
”.tniop taht litnu pu efil ym ni gnihtyna rebmemer t’nod I
.elihw a rof mih dessik dna
saw em devol ohw nam eht dna
,taht rof tnew I ,sevlehs pohs eht ni sttesuhcassaM notsoB rof sngis was I nehW .pohs eht dnuora kool ot kcen ym denarc I
”.DI sa ti elots enoemos ro daed s’eh rehtiE
.hturt eht mih dlot I ,htaerb peed a gnikaT
ylgnimees ,desserd tog I
dna uoy llik ot yaw wen a dedeen eH
.tekcop taht morf dah I gnir eht gnillup dna
.em edisni tsap eht fo noitcellocer elttil emoS
deddon eh erofeb ,snoitpo sih dessessa
.deksa I ”?em pandik ot deirt ohw elpoep eht fo eno …wonk’y
”.fo wonk I taht ton ,gnissim mih detroper s’ydobon
.srehto gnoma yaB apmaT dna
.lufesu eb dluow otni tius dlo fo sdrahs eht ffuts dluoc I llams gnihtemos gnivah yllaedi hguoht ,dah I tahw detcelloc I
.emocrevo dluoc I tahw dnoyeb raf em derebmuntuo yeht sa ecnatsiser on dereffo I
,kcurtsbmud tahwemos ,em ta derats regdab ehT
”?deneppah tahW ?thgirla uoy erA
,moor eht dnuora gnivaew seye ,detalfed eH
.ffo ekat ot evom ew sa sdnuop traeh yM
tuB“ .denialpxe yrreP ”.tiucric aidem eht ni esle enoemos s’eh ,haeY“
.dat a gnitatiseh mih leef dluoc I dna
.txen saw eh wenk I
”?pirt eht morf gnihtyna rebmemer uoy od …thgirlA“
?em rebmemer t’nod uoY“
.latem eht otni dessobme ti dnuora srewolf fo nrettap a
.uoy fo dir teg ot yaw rehtona yrt dluoc eh os esle enoyreve morf yawa uoy teg ot dah eh
.letoh etanro rehtar a
daeh ym ta gnimia morf dils
dehca I tub ,tfos saw ssarg eht
,em sllac dna snur yrreP“ .deddon
.roolf eht no ylsselpleh liaw dna repmihw ylno dluoc tub teef sih ot teg ot deirt etoyoc ehT
hateehc ehT ”.em rebmemer t’nod uoy esuaceb
.retlehS  .pleH  .emoH
,dekrab I ”!tihslluB“ dennirg kcaJ
;drawrof deppets yrreP .redluohs sih ot
dna regnif sih otno ti desae I
.deciton ylsuoiverp t’ndah I gnihtemos dettops I ,did I sA
.em pleh ylbaborp dluoc enoemos denokcer I os ,hguoht letoh yknaws a saw sihT
.tsilaiceps lavivrus on m’I dna laitnesse eb dluow esehT
.seye ym otni ylpeed derats dna
.desuap neht ,em sdrawot dereggats eH
.esruoc fo ,siht em dlot yllautca d’eh taht toN
.taht naht repeed gud ev’d’yeht ,ofni rof gniggid saw enoemos fi
taob taht no tfel uoY“
,hO“ .kcab selims eH
.tnelis saw revird ehT
,repeekpohs a erew yehT
.deksa I ”?gnola gnimoc uoy t’nerA“
.ssik eht nruter ot tseb ym did I ,kciR rof lamron eb tsum siht gnimussA .ddo yrev
.dias hateehc ehT ”.yldalG“
”.diarfa m’I evah ew gab ylno eht si sihT“
”.tohs tsal eht tnaw I ,tsrif uoY“
.ti no eman eht saw ecallaW kciR
.tropssap s’knarF dah llits yrreP desilaer I nehw depmuj traeh yM
taht noitasilaer gnilttar ,elbatrofmocnu eht yb skcart ym ni deppots saw I nehw tius siht dekcerw gnivah rof tuo flesym ssuc ot tnew I taht tniop siht ta saw tI
.tsehc ym htiw level nug eht gnidloh dna pu gnidnats ,dias eH
.rodirroc ertnec eht otni mih ward ot elsia gnitaes eht ni kcab deppets I
.tropria sassanaM ta camrat eht no er’ew ,setunim 51 nihtiW .seitud rehto sih ot kcab ylksirb yaw sih sekam dna sdon eH
.thgirW knarF deman hateehc a fo saw eno siht tub ,tropssap a ,nehT
,roolf eht ot delpmurc yrreP
W“ .gnidnal eht ot timmoc ot werc thgilf eht gniredro ,tipkcoc eht ot yaw sih edam yrreP dna ecilpmocca eht no deniart nug sih tpek knarF .nwod doots dna
.sredluohs ym no swap
,mih rof reisae hcum ti edam evd’taht
.enohpelet eht ot derutseg saw I ,pohs sih otni yaw ym gnikaM
.gnir revlis sih tuo dellup dna tekcop tekcaj sih otni dehcaer I
,ylluferac erom kool ot detrats I
,degnahc nalp emag s’kcaJ neht os ,haeY“
”.epahs pot ni uoy deen I dna ,worromot mlif ot wohs a tog ew ,siht fo yna tuoba tegrof ew dna taht ni teg uoY
.deplug dna desuap eh ,tniop siht ta hguoht
.no dehsarc uoy taht taob eht no yug emos no ti detnalp dna
saw I desilaer I
.moor eht ni VT a saw erehT
.deddon I ,nialpmoc ot noitisop on nI
,ffuc eht ot woble eht morf ti ni spir taerg erew erehT
.rehtegot seceip eht fo yna tup t’ndluoc I os moor letoh eht fo tuo em detnaw eH“
”.uoy ecalper ot elbanu eb ot
.rail a ton m’I tub
,em sdrawot daor eht pu gniklaw
.esle enoyna rof dekool I dna
,dias eH ”.setunim 01 ni kcab eb ll’I ,ylkciuq sgniht ruoy rehtaG“ .dias I
.lennahc swen eht ot kcab nward saw noitnetta ym ,ti hcraeser dna yrt ot moor eht ni senizagam eht fo eno pu kcip ot tnew I sA
.elims a htiw dias eH ”.rennid rof emit ni emoh nwo ruoy fo trofmoc dna htmraw eht otni uoy teg ll’eW“
”.diarfa m’I lla ta gnihtoN“ .daeh ym koohs I
.deddon neht ,tropssap eht revo dekool flow ehT
.evisnepxe teg ot gniog saw sihT
”.won litnU .deraeppasid …dna
.tluciffid eb dluow ,elpoep thgir eht ot ti teg ot woh ,noitamrofni eht htiw od ot tahw
,ddo saw siht …saw sihT
.tropriA sassanaM morf dekoob enalp etavirp a tog ev’I .kroY weN ot pu kcab uoy teg ot tog ev’eW“
.denialpxe eH ”.owt ti ekam ton rehtar d’I ,keew siht tpmetta noitanissassa eno devivrus evah uoy ,riS“
.evE s’raeY weN .8791 ni taht uoy evag I“ .deddon flow ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.revird eht ot evig ot snoitcerid eht em def dna saw ti erehw wenk yrreP ,ylikcuL
.dloc yllauqe ,niaga ylper I ”.sknaht oN“
mra eht yb em gnikat ,dennirg yrreP
edis tsae eht no krap eht ta
.sredluohs sih gnidnif swap ym
.yrreP htiw gnineve eht dneps ot nwod delttes I ,gnineve eht rof flesmih desucxe dah knarF ecnO
.detpurretni I ”.os thguoht I ,haeY“ “
.knarF yletinifed saw ti
.edisa em dehsurb dna elpoep neewteb evom ot deunitnoc neht
.roolf eht no ynoga ni dnuora gnihtirw etoyoc eht nopu ylerauqs dexif seye ym tpek I
redluohs s’etoyoc eht ot
sih tsniaga spil ym decalp I
.gnir a tuo dellup dna tekcaj tius sih otni dehcaer eH
.xof der a fo saw erutcip ehT
,elbatrofmoc saw tI
,dias I ”.hcum os uoy knaht ,tnecifingaM“
.saw I ohw wonk yltcaxe t’ndid I
.moor eht gnivael dna yletilop pu gnidnats daetsni ,flesmih deppots tub ,tcejbo ot devom flow ehT
”thgirW knarF fo etaF ehT“   yojne esaelP
.deksa I ”?won sneppah tahw ,oS“
.gnineppah saw tahw htiw spirg ot teg retteb d’I desilaer I ,gnivil a rof did I tahw saw siht fI
.dehgual etoyoc ehT ”?ew t’nera ,luftegroF“
”?uoy era erehw ,riS“
.deddon tub ,flesmih evorp ot gnideen yb delbuort demees eH
tuo uoy dedeen eh ,taht teg oT
tub …gnihtyna rebmemer t’nod I“ .daeh ym koohs I
,sih fo etaicossa na htiw gnola
.draob no em swollof dna stneler etoyoc ehT
.em ta ylerauqs detniop erew htob won dna nug s’yrreP koot knarF
.riahc eht ni nwod kcab tas I ,nilanerda no knurD
.derewoc dna roolf eht ot evod I ,gniddew a ta kcirp eraps a sa lufesu sa saw I gnisilaeR .ytpmE .kcilC
.hguoht noitats VT emos no tols emityad diloS
a em morf yawa gninrut mih hctaw I
.derettum I ”.gnimoc siht ees t’ndid tsomla I ,sey hA“
,seiromem ruoy tsol uoy taht tuo dekrow evah
flesym gnitpurretni erofeb
.suoicsnocbus ym fo tuo mih tuoba gnihtyna
”?eb thgim thgirW knarF ohw wonk uoy oD“
.dehca I yldab woh leef ylreporp
.sksa etoyoc ehT ”?srinevuoS“
?kciR yako uoy erA“
morf gnieb sa em decalp tug yM
.erus rof deyalp eh elor tahw wonk t’nod I tub ,taob eht no saw knarF
…lleW“ .hgis a koot eH
.tcatni tfel saw taht
.delbuort dekool yletinifed eh ,em ta kool ot yawa dellup eh sA
hguoht ,deilper elidocorc ehT ”der eht attuo em teg ot ffuN‘ .neppah siht ekam ot hsac fo tol a desimorp tog I“
.yltpurba detfihs enot ehT
.dnah ni nug ,niaga em ot denrut eH
.htuom ym tfel sdrow eht sa gnilkcub traeh sih raeh dluoc I
devirra tius a ni yug ymils a nehw elpoep ot stnuocca evig ot gninnigeb saw I
.siht od ot evah t’nod eW“ .dias I ”,netsiL“
.was I nosrep tsrif eht deppots dna renroc teerts a ot ti edam I
”?uoy era stuobaerehW“
,yaw rehtie uoy evol I“
.tius paehc a ni depparw elidocorc ralucsum a
.esu yna fo eb ot gniog saw ereh gnihtoN
.nageb I ”…gnihtemos evah od I
.skool ti sa raelc sa si siht lla fi ,esruoc fo ,si tahT
.dereffo flow ehT
.deksa I ”?won ti si raey tahW“
.noitazilivic ees dluoc I ,ecnatsid raf oot ton eht nI
.teef sih ot pu kcab depmuj yrreP
.hateehc gnikool-railimaf a yb dniheb morf daeh eht ot tih
,”.kciR ,ruonoh na neeb s’tI“ yas d’I“
.derednop yrreP ”?I mA“
.ylsuoixna deredduhs eh dna ,denekaew nug eht fo pirg siH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.denialpxe tnadnetta ehT
,RP dab si RP dab ,uoy llet attog I od semit ynam woh ,kciR netsiL“
.seton derapmoc dna sknird emos dah ,nwod tas eW
.ti otni dessobme srewolf htiw
”.emit siht ti rebmemer ll’uoy ebyam os ,raeh uoy eman tsal eht eb ll’tI“ .dias
.mih ot ti gniwohs ,dias I ”.oot esoht fo eno evah I“
.edisni deppets I dna denepo rood ehT
.tsrif saw taht ohw ksa ot esiw neeb evah dluoW .deplug I
gnineppah saw tahw aedi yna
.sgniht ym gnirehtag dna pu gnidnats
”!?uoy oD“ .delrans eH ”.eman ym rebmemer neve t’nod uoy teb I
,gnidliub dlo rehtar ,egral a sdrawot detrocse dna rac eht fo tuo nekat saw I
.moor eht gnivael
.yrreP dna erutcip eht neewteb gnikool ,niaga hpargotohp eht rof dehcaer I
em dedeen eh dna ,erutcip eht fo
.xofnogard reppad
.tius derettat eht fo tuo desserdnu I
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.stros lla ,srotagitsevni ,enecs eht no scidem erew ereht ,nooS
.”reh htiw laed a ekaM“ ,”mih htiw esiaiL“
.boj ruoy detnaw kcaJ ,oS“ .deddon knarF
-kroY weN morf er’uoY .ecallaW kciR si eman ruoy ,1891 s’ti ,os ,yakO“
tohsnug a yb ffo tuc saw tub ,nageb eH ”-uoy did woH“
”.ecaps erom elttil a evresed uoy ,enif s’tI“
evael dna rezalb ym ffo ekat I
.knuj dna steknirt tsuj lla saw tI
.erus rof wenk I lla tsomla s’tI
.rood eht dekcol ylteiuq
”.ytic kroY weN fo tuo ,CBN no ,’hctiP giB
?egoots a saw ereh yrreP fi tahW .desuap I tub
”thgirW knarF fo etaF ehT“ saw sihT
llup ot yaw a dnif t’ndluoc I fi ees ot erutcip eht no seye eht otni peed kool ot deirt I
gnir revlis llams a saw tI
.ylleJ YK rof retset etsat eht ekil dekooL .yug rednels ,etoyoc a saw eH
,tnedicca gnitaob a ni devlovni neeb tsuj ev’I“
”.deniatrecsa gnieb llits si egdirbdooW ot tog eh woh hguoht
.dias I ”.ainigriV ,egdirbdooW ni m’I tuo snruT
”’?hctiP giB ehT‘ morf yug eht uoy t’nera …uoy esingocer I …I
…hhu tub enalp eht gnihsarc ton otni stolip eht nurrevo dna tuo pmuj ot gniog tsuj erew ew ,haeY“
,llebpmaC yrreP m’I“ .deddon flow ehT
.rae ot rae gninnirg ,dias kcaJ ”?I t’noW“
.kcaJ rof mussop yalp ot ediced I
.wap s’tnadnetta delttesnu ylgnisaercni eht gnikahs dna pu gnidnats
,kroY weN etatspu
selegnA soL ,otnoroT ,atreblA rof sngis erew ereht noitasilaer eht ta
.dedderhs tius ,seceip ni taob ,camotoP eht fo knab eht no ot-emac I“ .deddon I
lennahc swen eht htiw deteerg noos saw I tub ,pu mraw ot tnemom a koot tI
.mlac fo tnemom a saw ereht dna desolc rood ehT
.egabrag rieht gnitomorp sllabemils ssenisub gnimoc-dna-pu htiw wohs tahc emoS
tsrub reilrae morf etoyoc eht dna nepo nworht saw rood eht ,ylper dluoc I erofeB
.flog gniyalp eb ot deraeppa ew dna
.noisneherppa htiw em ta gnikool
.did eh ekil egdurg a dah I mih dlot tsuj I
.staes eht neewteb gnirewoc
,tsurt dluoc I tlef I nam ylno eht ,yrreP
”?emosdnah ,elttil a yromem ym goj pleh uoy tuoba woH“
”?pleh uoy nac ,tsol neeb evah yam enoemos kniht I
tub ainigriV ,egdirbdooW
.deddon I .denialpxe eH
.yrreP ta gnitniop
.em morf elots uoy tropssap ym em dewohs eh ,em dlot yrreP“
.pot eht revo depard ti
”.ecin yreV“ .yltruc ylper I ”.seY“
.etoyoc eht ta ylerauqs detniop nug sih
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
lufraF lacsaP yb
.oot kcab ym morf gnilgnad cirbaf eht fo emos
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.rehtael kcalb ,dloC
.tey toN .ti noitseuq ot emit evah t’ndid I
”.gnir taht uoy evag I
.denialpxe knarF ”.txen eb ot gniog saw I wenk I“
,detsisni I ”.nalp eht htiw pu emac dna tropssap eht mih evag ,no gniog saw tahw knarF dlot ohw eno eht erew uoY“
gnihtemos dessim d’I esac ni tsuj egakcerw eht fo revo kcehc lanif eno did dna teef ym ot tog I
.em naht retteb erew uoy ekil detca syawla uoY“
etoyoc ehT ”.reklaW kcaJ“
.pu dda etiuq t’ndid …ro
denialpxe I ”.rovivrus ylno eht eb thgim I kniht I
.thgir gnihtemos gniod eb tsum I os moor letoh siht dna omil a evah ot mees I
.moor ym ot pu em del neht
.drah oot gnihsup
.hguoht seimene emos evah thgim I yhw nialpxe dluoW
…ton er’uoy wonk I od woH“
.em ot kcab dekool eh ,enola etoyoc eht dna em htiw woN
,hcihw ,oot enalp eht no kcaJ gnirb did uoY“
,kcaJ ot ti detrulb uoy esac ni tsuj  ,taht uoy llet dluoc I taht toN
.flesym tneiro em pleh ot gniog t’nsaw
.knarF dna yrreP htiw gnola emoh kcab detrocse saw I
hcihw ,erofeb ainigriV ot gniog reve rebmemer t’ndid I
”.od ll’ew tahw erus ton
.tops ecin rehtar a saw emoH
.latipsoh ot nekat dna
.em dessik dna enim ot spil sih tup eh ,dekcilc sgniht sa tsuJ
,tnorf eht raen pu tas si etoyoc ehT
”?kniht uoy t’nod ,sdneirf htiw gniylf og ot ecin si erus tI“
.tropriA ytrebiL kraweN ta nwod dehcuot ew ,yllanif tub
ehT‘ ,wohs VT eht fo tsoh eht er’uoy dna ,thgirlA“
,enizagam eht hguorht gnikooL
.tniop doog a edam eH
.enim dnuof noos siH
.wap tnanimod sih htiw dnuow sih revoc dluoc eh os dnah ffo sih ni won nug ,mra gnideelb sih dehctulc kcaJ ”.pu s’emag ehT
.enizagam eht dna tropssap s’knarF neewteb dekool I
”?era ew erehw wonk ot neppah uoy od tub ,yrros m’I ,em esucxE“
eht,nelarD yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
sih morf nug s’etoyoc eht debbarg I
,sniart gnitalumis emit sih sdneps ohw
,kcehc ot em no tropssap eht evah ot deen t’ndid I
,neeb evah thgim taht ohw tuo krow dna yrt ot dah I serutcip eht ta dekool I
yrots s’yadoT dna
tekcaj tius yttat eht ot gnilbmarcs ,dias I ”,seY“
,citamuenp saw ti ekil
”.ecalp ni thgir yug llaf a evah I“
.kroY weN dnalsI gnoL morf ecnaraeppasid sih gniwollof ainigriV egdirbdooW ni detacol neeb sah ecallaW kciR tsoh noisiveleT
.tsael ta yromem ym ot ,lleW
.tegrof uoy tel dluow hsarc taob a neve ton ,sgniht emoS .sey hA
,”ereht em ekaT“ ,”siht em kooB“
.dias etoyoc ehT ”.thgir erew uoy sseug I ,kciR yeH“
.senob ym ni ti leef tsuj dluoc I
.eurt saw ti decnivnoc yltcefrep ton ,dias I ”.seY“
.deplug eh dna no gnir eht deppils I
.os kniht t’nod I“
.oot drawrof deppets dah etaicossa s’etoyoc ehT
.tropssap eht tuo llup I ,kcab gnir eht gnittuP
.detnap kcaJ ”?woH ?yhw-
?tius ym siht saW
.yssalC .depirtsniP
.daeh sih debbur dna delkcuhc eH ”?taht wonk uoy
.em rof tuo ssalg a gnidloh ,dias eH ”?knird ot gnihtemos tuoba woH“
em was uoy emit yrevE .no deklaw uoy trid eht ekil em detaerT
.gab gnillor egral yrev a htiw deraeppa tnadnetta na ,gnol erofeB
,hguoht tropssap s’knarF dah I ecnO
?ecivres moor taht si ,olleH“
.tluaf ruoy s’taht tuB“
.pu gnignah erofeb ,dias yehT ”.yaw ym no m’I ,thgirlA“
”.daed si thgirW knarF dellac yug a kniht I dna ecallaW kciR si eman ym wonk tsuj I .ma I ohw ro ,ma I erehw wonk t’nod I
.ylteiuq devom rac ehT
.edisni gnireep ,gab eht denepo dna nwod dettauqs I ,tnadnetta eht gniyE
rekcit llams a deciton I
.yrasrevda gniniamer eht sdrawot deppets knarF
”.em eveileb ,kciR og ot ti detnaw I woh t’nsi sihT“
,siht fo lla dniheb saw ohw aedi dilos a dah won I sa hcum sA
.seye sih ni cinap a s’ereht ,gniyl s’eh taht ees nac I
”.wonk uoy sruoh wef a uoy evas ll’tI“
.dnalsI gnoL no nodgnitnuH fo htroN
.knarF ot revo dekool eH ”.kciR eybdooG
,nwod tas dna hcae retaw fo ssalg a detcelloc eW .peew ot detrats
.won mih detsurt I tuB .rebmemer t’ndid I
,serawanu tahwemos thguac saw I taht raelc neeb evah tsum tI
,edisni em detrocse yehT
.dedda hateehc ehT ”.uoy rof tsuj ,kcab nug ytpme na tpek eW“
dna redluohs ym ni daeh sih deirub eH
taht tnemom a rof deirrow I
,detatiseh elidocorc ehT
.dnalsI gnoL dnuora pirt lanoitomorp a no og ot deksa erew uoy ,oga keew a tuoba neht os ,yako ,thgirlA“
,aes ta tsol enoemos s’erehT .tnedicca gnitaoB“
”.doog yna uoy od ot gniog ton s’ti esuaceb
,swen eht revo lla si ffuts siht desilaer I
,elor s’knarF gnirevocnu otni troffe hcum tup t’ndid uoy epoh I“
.mret mumitpo eht gnieb ”saW“
m’I enog seiromem ruoy htiW .yllaer wonk t’nod I
,dnalhsram eht otni gud doow fo stib dettops I ,dnuora gninruT
.tsoh ot demees I wohs VT eht no egap a dnuof I
.dnuora gniyl sesactius dna sexob
”.did knarF dna em ,lleW“
.deddon I ”…wonk’y
.elidocorc eht ta ti detniop dna ydob gniliaw
.erehwemos nwod ssalg eht gnittup
tub esruoc fo trepxe na saw I taht toN
”?rebmun enohp sih tog uoY“
si sihT“ .desuap ehS
.detpurretni I ”.eid t’ndid I tuB“
.regna htiw deslup ecaf siH
.ylkciuq deddon neht
I tub ,eugnot ym fo pit eht no pird dna elgnad ot demees eman yM
hguoht ,ffuc-eht-ffo os noitamrofni fo dnik taht tuo gnidnah neeb evah t’ndluohs yllaitnetop I
,niaga regna htiw seslup eH
tcefrep elgnis a ni
”.edis ym yb nam tseb ym evah ot ekil d’I ,niaga em llik ot seirt enoemos fI“
.”.no troper dluoc uoy taht ecitsuj fo egairracsim cigart a ekil kool d’ti ,txen em rof tnew uoy nehw nehT
.mih ecaf ot doots I
”?rebmemer ,gnippandik a devivrus tsuj uoY ?stseug diova ot uoy dlot I thguoht I“
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dnik emos fo etaicossa ssenisub a ylbaborp erew yeht derugif I
.dias eH ”.em ot tniop sregnif lla ,sraeppasid yug rehtO
.egap ytiniffAruF sih no
.lennahc swen lacol a otno dekcilf dna no ti denrut I
.dias eH ”.siht esingocer dluohs uoy ,em rebmemer t’nod uoy fi nevE“
,don degdelwonkca-flah a em evag eH
.kciR etuc s’tahT“ ”.tsomlA“
.mra eht fo evaw a evag etoyoc ehT .dennirg I
.moordeb eht ot ffo em gnidael dna
eht,nelarD yb uoy rof daer ,lufraF lacsaP yb
.noitseuq tnellecxE
.delims kcaJ ”.emas eht yas nac ereh enoyreve toN
dna rehtegot egdirB nylkoorB ssorca deklaw eW
.rekaerbtraeh a sa hcum flesym deicnaf reven I
”?eb thgim uoy kniht I“
.ti hcaer t’ndluoc tsuj
detserra ,tsrif enalp eht ffo nekat saw kcaJ
.uoy si ti dog hO“
”.kroY weN ot ti ekam ot gniog era su fo lla ton …ees uoy ,seY“ .dat
”?lleb a gnir eman taht seod
,ssap ot emit gnol a koot ruoh nA
.elkraps ot demees em edisni gnihtemoS
.dettimda I ”.t’nod I“
.dedda yrreP ”.daeh ruoy otni yrots wen a tnalpmi tsuj dluoc eh
.emit doog a gnivah tuo neeb evah tsum I .revo lla
,dias I ”.od nac I tahw ees ll’I ,ereht tiaW“
.taht ekil erehwemos ,acitU
seye sih otni dekool I
”?gab a evah I dluoc ,seY
.tsaot a rof ssalg sih pu gnidloh
.riahc eht no kcab denael dna delbmurg eH
”.yawyna ti htiw yawa teg t’now uoY .egnahc nac I
.meht neewteb ecnatsid eht gnisolc ylwols dna
”.pukcab artxe sa uoy htiw enalp eht no yaw sih selggums yrreP