,ytinutroppo na otni siht nrut dluoc eh spahreP
.detcejretni yksuh eht
a dellac evah dluow eh tahw erow yksuh ehT
".tneinel eb thgim egduj eht ,ylteiuq emoc uoy fI
.ria eht otni flesreh dehcnual dna
,sevlesmeht delrufnu sgniw fo riap evissam a sa
.dedihc ehs ",on ,on ,on ,hO"
smaes eht ta trapa tsrub kcab reh no kcap eht
"?neeb ereht evah erom ynam woH" .dehguoc eH
”xirtaivA ehT“:yojne esaelP
.kcen reh dnuora ylesool gnignah selggog fo tes a dah neve ehS
aT" .dnuor nups ylwols yksuh ehT
.gniggaw saw ehS ...saw ehS
,htooms saw eciov reH
.demra saw ehs esac ni
.nem sih no dednuor eh
.uoy llac yeht ,xirtaivA taerG ehT" .ereht erew
sevlesmeht gnidnetxe
.ecnis tuo ro ni og enoyna nees t'nevah syob yM .uoy detcatnoc ew nehw s'taht dna ,edisni dethgis saw ehS .tuo dekats ecalp eht dah I ,hcnuh a nO
tseb sih fo wef a ot detniop godllub ehT
,tsrif og nem sih gnittel
.sserP flowafoS ta rotide
,looc saw ria eht ,pot pU
.emit sih koot eH
,revel neddih a fo llup a htiw dna
.ti revo lla sthgilhcraes thgirb gninihs
".stsieh nezod a dniheb feiht suoinegni ehT
,edisni ymirg dna krad saw tI
.srevlover rieht fo ttub eht dnuor dehctulc rehto eht dna
.deltsirb godllub ehT
.troper sih hsinif ot deirt dna denethgiarts reirret ehT ".rotcepsni
.foor eht fo egde eht tsniaga denael ohw
.rotcepsni feihc ,ris ,seY"
.muesum eht otni mih wollof ot meht denoitom dna
.og ot erehwon evah uoY"
sriats eht rof yletaidemmi edam eH
tinU lacituanoreA eciloP nodnoL ehT
,foor eht sdrawot dna
.tnellecxe ,tnellecxE"
.kcab reh ssorca ylthgit depparts kcapkcab egral a dah ehs dna
saw sihT.xirtaivA eht
.desuap dna muesum eht sdrawot pets a koot eH ".flesym
,yksuh gninnirg emas eht ta detniop lla erew slerrab xis dna
.seye sih erofeb hsalf reerac sih gniees
.emit siht derenroc reh tog eW"     dnE kraD yb
.ecaf eritne reh ssorca denediw dah elims reH ".lliw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ecnatsid eht ni gnilbmur ylteiuq saw semahT eht
.seye reh revo pu selggog eht dellup ehs dnah eno htiW
.yad doog a hcus saw ti ,hO
.flesmih ot delims eH
,ewa ni depag elbatsnoc eht fo tsoM
.godllub eht ot pu nar reirret A
.oga ruoh na flah aera eht ni enalp reh was eW"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tius s'tsilbigirid deifidom
?enalp a no retne I esuaceb xirtaivA eht em llac yeht kniht uoy oD"
.rotcepsni feihc ,at-
.flesym reh no sffuc eht tup ot tnaw I
.napsgniw toof 21 lluf a ot
.siht rof noitomorp a teg uoy erus ekam ll'I tub
.erac t'ndid rotcepsni feihc eht tub
".yllautneve tuo dnif ll'I"
sdnah reh ni saw egakcap depparw A
,sffup wef a koot ,ti til
.dednuorrus si gnidliub ehT
,ria eht dellif rethgual s'xirtaivA eht sA
,dnE kraD yb ”xirtaivA ehT“
:eno rebmun ymene dna ,seY
thgit no seibbob rieht gnidloh dnah eno htiw gninnur
".ysae oot boj ruoy ekam ot tnaw ton od I"
.egap noertaP ro ,yrruFoS
,srepap eht ni tiderc eht teg yam I
,ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
etuhcarap a fo sniamer dedracsid ehT
.tnemom eht derovaS
.revlover sih dekcoc eno tub
.ereh morf ti hsinif ot ni syob wef a ekat ll'I" .deunitnoc dna
,dnE kraD yb ”xirtaivA ehT“
,selbatsnoc htiw gnimraws erew sdaor ehT
.gnippirt pu dedne ylno tub
.esolc pu reh gniees emit tsrif sih saw tI
.enalp a fo relleporp eht sa tsaf sa mih dniheb gniggaw saw liat siH
.selbigirid wef a naht secruoser erom dedeen ecilop nodnoL eht woh
.godllub dlo gnikool hsiroob a detleb ",nem ,retsaF
.ragic sih fo dne eht ta depmohc godllub ehT   ".gnorw etiuQ
ylpmis dias ehs ",gnivaeL"
.tniaf thgim tsuj eh deticxe os dekool reirret ehT "!ris ,uoy knahT"   ".siht
.htaerb rof depsag eH "...rotcepsni feihC"
.dednamed godllub ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,foor eht fo egde eht ot ylwols deklaw godllub eht dna delbmarcs nem ehT   "!reh retfa teG
.gnorw s'tahT .on hO
.ragic eht hguorht thgiarts depmohc
,gnidliub eht no deniart srevlover
,muesum eht otno degrevnoc selbigirid ecilop fo oirt a ,evoba pu raF
si yrots s’yadot dna
.teef reh ot esor dna dehgual yksuh ehT
?rof gnitiaw uoy era tahw ,lleW"
.ragic sih morf ffup a koot rotcepsni feihc ehT
"?gniod uoy era tahW"
,detuohs godllub ehT "!loof uoy ,oN"
,noitisop evisnefed a ni tlenk dah maet s'rotcepsni feihc eht fo tser eht ,mih dnuora llA ".potfoor
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
"?retemirep eht pu tes uoy evaH"
.tnaegras ,yrrow uoy t'noD"
",tuoba wonk uoy tahT"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
".srepap eht llet ot gnihtemos evah ot tnaw I
.potfoor eht no neeb dah ehs ,selbigirid eht morf drow deviecer ew tsaL
".lraep eht tih thgim uoY"
,ragic a tuo dellup godllub ehT ".tnellecxe
.sroirepus sih ot siht nialpxe ot gniog saw eh woh gnikniht
.citarcotsira tsomla
.lla ti fo ecnedupmi ehT
.dlihc tnelosni na ekil mih gnitaert saw ehS
.lliw uoy kniht ton od I"
,mih evoba hgih saw selbigirid fo murht eht
.eman ruoy em llet tsael tA"
".esufer tsum I diarfa ma I"
.ti ot gnir ecin a dah
,deraor rotcepsni feihc eht "!deppart er'uoY"
)denosaer eh ,lraep eht neeb evah tsum taht(
.eye sih thguac noitom gnirettulf a sa edis eht ot decnalg godllub ehT
.od dluow ti doog eht lla rof
,reh hctac ot deirt dah selbatsnoc eht fo enO
,gniredloms seye ,godllub ehT
.dne na ta ecneitap sih
trats pets-eerht a koot ehS ".emit txen liT