,derovaf snoitidnoc fi ,thgim ehs dna
.kcen sih fo edis eht otni degnulp dah asuL efink eht ta gnihctulc sdnah
feilebsid ni tnemom a reh no desucof rehto eht elihw ,etihw enohs
.niaga dehgual ehS
,erots sdoog gnitrops a fo sniur eht morf degavlas
.detseggus ehs ”,yawyna ni emoC“
,thgin sselpeels A .ti enod dah ehS
.daeh reh ni eb ot neve ton
,denethgil dna denniht dah sduolc eht ees dluoc ehs dna
,noitidnoc sih ni nam a ot deirram gnieb reh rof yrros tlef ohw
reh ekat dluoc emarf ehtil reh sa tsaf sa llih eht pu dehsad dna
;pots ot ti teg ot elbanu neeb dah ehs tub
.ti draeh ehs erofeb ecaf reh yb zihw tellub eht tlef ehS
,kcap reh ni pmup dnah a dah ehS
,neeb evah tsum ti tahw tuo elzzup retal dluow ehS
,detneler dah mrots ehT
.knis mih gnihctaw
”,tuo m’I ,ti s’tahT“
”?ylrig-ylerriuqs ,nug BB elttil ruoy nwod tup uoy t’nod yhW“
,tisnart eht etelpmoc dluoc ehs erofeb reh no saw ,hsalf a sa tsaf
elkna reh dnuora depmalc dnah sih
,peels uoy fI“ .dias ti
taob a otno yaw reh retrab dluow ehs erehT
drayparcs eht ni kcab esoom eht htiw dah d’ehs noitasrevnoc fo sdnartS
”?erom emos peels ot tnaw uoy oD
.ti gnitset morf hcum taht wenk ehS
”!og ti tel tsuj ,eduD“
.kcahs sih ot rood eht fo wodniw krad eht ot dexif eton a saw ereht was tub
.thgil-eborts a ekil saw
,seenk sih otno sdrawkcab delbmuf dna reh desaeler eH
,taebtraeh reh fo mhtyhr eht dna
nekrad ot nageb yks eht nehw
.ereht llifdnal eht egnevacs ot stnemegnarra edam dna
,ehca llud a ot gnibmun
,dnuow eht otni pu deggard yllaitrap dna degdolsid ,llabeye thgir siH
.noziroh eht ssorca eriw nedlog a ekil
msilabinnac ot troser ot nugeb evah aera eht ni stidnab taht demrofni neeb tsuj dah ehS
.enobtsaerb sih fo elddim eht ni thgir
laudarg os gnissap s’mrots eht
”,tar-eert ,yap annog er’uoY“
.egnar taht ta reh tih ot gniyrt pu nevig evah tsum sreusrup reh
.edisni efil s’ikiM dna reh fo hcum oot dah ti
.eybdoog mih ssik dna
.uoy no kcehc ot retal yb eb ll’rotcod ehT“
.ssalg a rof dnuora gnilttar mih draeh ehs erehw
.pot eht revo yaw eht fo tser eht
yticolev ’sgniraeb-llab eht tub
;sih ni dnah reh koot eH .truh tI
,secnatsmucric reh gnidrager erehw dna yhw eht fo niatrecnu ,wons eht ni pu tas ehS
,ereht deretsloh lotsip a dah eh taht
.detalumucca dah taht sehsid ytrid fo niatnuom eht enigami ylno dluoc ehs
.revo gnizalg erofeb
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,elawD yb
.emit lanif dna tsrif eht rof hguoht sa
.htgnerts gnimlehwrevo elohw sih
,hsalps a htiw retaw eht otni deppit dna deretlaf tub
sllihtoof nedal-ecurps eht ni erehT
,taht naht erom gnihton
.dniwlrihw a ekil edisa sreirrab eht peews dluow ehs
.hguorht neeb dah ehs tahw retfa detcepxe eb ot saw taht desoppus tub
.reh pots dluoc gnihtoN
,ssenlluf ot denepo seye reh dna
yznerf sselkcer a ni epols eht nwod gnihsad stidnab eht fo owt was ehs nehw ylnO .deunitnoc
.tserof eht hguorht deohce kcarc citamuenp prahs A “-
spmup-dnah erusserp-hgih morf rehtegot deceip d’ehs noitpartnoc ydleiwnu na saw tI
,derram reverof eb thgim llew os devol dna desiarp dah ikiM reh liat eht taht
,derebmemer ehs ,ereht tuo stidnab owt llits erew erehT
dnoces eht saw sihT
ria reh no eguag erusserp eht dekcehc dna
.stohs yffi no elbmag ot noitinumma no wol oot erew yeht spahreP
.enilerohs eht morf derelloh raguoc dlo eht
,nwaps ot emoc hsif htiw demeet sretaw ehT
regnis ,teop ,elawD yb
.sgnorp rebbur fo riap a saw lerrab eht nwod gnillor morf ti tpek taht lla ,rebmahc gnirif eht otni omma tel ot tlob eht dellup ehs ecnO
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
reh nopu tey ton saw ti tub
.erofeb morf eciov sih wenk ehS
,yks eht otni raf
.tey reh dellik t’ndah yeht ,llitS
.revir eht fo ecnatsid gnituohs nihtiw saw ehs dna
.suoires eb tsum dnuow eht wenk ehs hguoht
.sknabrevir eht nwod deohce taht eno drah a
yks eht otni ,llihpu
,dnuof dah sretnuh reh dna ehs htob
,tius gnorts sih t’nsaw gnipeekesuoH
”.ykcul erew uoY .yretra na nrot evah dluow ti dna rewol retemillim a flaH
.regnif a fo htgnel eht niks fo palf a eerf deppir dna
,taob eht otni raeg reh gnuls ehs
,epols eht pu yllufreehc sgel gnihca reh derrups ehS
won was ehs elcarim siht fo spirg eht ni
,tfird wons a ni dnif reh neddih dah ehs
.nalp a ekil hcum yrev gnihtemos demrof ehs
;thgil wol ni ees ot slamina rehto swolla hcihw    eht kcal slerriuqS
.sllafretaw dna sloop eht revo tpael yeht sa
,thgiew eritne sih htiw nwod gnihsup dna gnizeeuqs
.sdrawpu tellub a detcelfed elcivalc ruoy dias rotcod ehT .haeY“ ”.tohs tog I“
.sgnidnuorrus reh ni koot ehs ,gninwaY
.regnevacs ykculnu na fo esproc eht morf sesnel gniyfingam fo esac a deniatbo dna
?doog saw taht ebyam tuB
seye reh tuhs ot naht erom gnihton dekil evah dluow ehs
,gnikaeps raguoc eht neeb evah tsum tahT
”.laed a tuo krow dna srehto eht htiw teem ll’ew ,retteb er’uoy nehW
.ti eciton ot deliaf dah ehs taht
,hcae erom eciwt derif yehT
.emoc ton did tcapmi dedaerd ehT
.won kniht dluoc ehs lla saw taht ,ti enod dah ehS
dnah sih morf llef nug ehT
elihw a eunitnoc dluoc ehs taht deifsitas saw ehs tub
,ria eht delpmas dna seye reh tuhs ehs
”!toidi ,rotom eht tratS“
,weiv otni emac ecaf s’dnabsuh reH
,sserP lesaeW yb dehsilbup
ecnef eht revo kcap eht devaeh ehs
.mih rof edam d’ehs ezepart eht htiw sserttam eht otno flesmih deluah dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
pets sselerac a edam enoemos litnu ton
.seye gniniarts reh morf thgil sti dna noom eht dih yeht dna
,dna retaw-revir yci eht htiw delgnim tnorf ehT
;nosrep reh revo elur hsrah sti detressaer scisyhp nehw tnemom eht tlef reven ehS
gnihcraes dna dliw
.ruoh eht yb gniworran lavivrus reh fo sddo eht
,tekcos eye eht fo egde eht no mih kcurts dah
yrrucs reh tel ot ,og tel dna pley mih ekam ot hguone saw ti tub ,hcum t’nsaw tI .pmuht delffum a htiw eson eht no mih detlep dna
.kcalb tnew dlrow reh
.nac ados a ekil tfarc munimula reh elpmurc dluow esoht fo owt neewteb deppart eb oT
,neddir ton ,dewot eb ot tnaem saw dels eht tub
htuom sih ssorca daerps elims a nehT
.meht revocer ot ni detrad dah ehs
,dnuorg elbats no neve tih ot tluciffid si tcejbo gnivom a tub
.spil reh no ”apaP“
,reh dnuora lla sredluob fo ezis eht seceip erew ereht tub
.tsaoc eht morf raf neeb evah t’ndluoc ehS
.gnils redluohs sti morf dnuora nug-ria reh thguorb ehS
.dnuow reh no tup d’ehs sserpmoc eht kcehc ot ralloc reh nwod ti kcuts dna dnah reh koot ehs ,gnihgiS
.drawno tnew dna ,enil dels reh deredluohs-er ,dehgis neht
,namowrehsif a ton elihw dna
htaerb deggar siH
saw ti tahw rof nug-ria eht gnizingocer
thgiarts staob rieht peek ot saw
.kcots a tuohtiw nugtohs fo ezis eht tuoba
ak“ gniyfsitas a edam hcihw ,desolc enizagam eht dleh taht
.neeb dah daeh reh erehw ecaps eht hguorht dessap sdnuor owt erofeb tsuj elttorht eht tih dna dekcud tub ,kool t’ndid ehS
,ecnavda ot deunitnoc yehT
.elbuort fo ngis tsrif eht ta retlehs ot deraperp saw dna
,teiuq-repsihw ,cirtcele erew yeht
.yticapac tnecrep xis-ytrof ta kcap-
.rednu mih dellup tnerruc eht erehw
.reh pots ot gnihton saw erehT
,gnicanem dna kciht
drow eht htiw ,gnipsag
llub a ekil kcarc A
:gnineppah saw gnizama erom neve gnihtemos tuB
,meht dna reh neewteb ecnatsid emos tup dah ehs ecnO
,esu ni ton nehw retaw eht fo tuo relleporp s’eonac eht dleh taht hctac eht desaeler ehs ,ydob reh fo edis tfel eht no hsiugna eht morf gnicniW
,liat reh fo dne eht hctac ot gnarps dna
,radec wolley sa nwonk osla
.seye tohsdoolb reh gnipiw
,gnireets ot kcab tnew eh dna
,sduolc eht ,yks eht hguorht
,taerht hcum ton erew eci fo sknuh rellams ehT
,reh ot tfel kcatta eno eht
.enola yleritne t’nsaw ehs ebyam tuB
,erofeb tnemom a nug-ria reh gnicarb neeb dah hcihw ,mra tfel reH
.tsal ta yrrauq rieht htiw pu thguac dah yeht dnuof yeht
,reh erofeb esor revir ehT
.reppiz sih dniheb eglub evissam a dna
reh dnuof hcihw enutrofsim eht taht
.sgnaf dewolley fo nirg a gnihsalf flow eht ,diarfanu
.llaf ti tel dna troffe eht ni tuo deirc ehs tub
.neddibnu yromem reh otni detaolf
,gnieb reh fo sessecer tsepeed eht morf dnim lamirp a
.ffo sreksihw reh fo eno deppilc taht tohsnug a reh denrae dah taht dna
wap suoretxed reh htiw
?ssob eht ot did ehs tahw retfA“
gnitacixotni tsomla saw retaw gninnur dna dniw fo dnuos ehT
,ti htiw detcennoc sliar eht nehw ,toor ehT
?retniw fo elddim eht ni gnirps eb ti dluoc woH
tellub A“ .tsac a ni neeb evah llew sa thgim ti taht
.wonk t’ndid ehs ,thgie ro ruof saw ti rehtehw tub
rettilg revlis ekil gninihs selacs rieht
tsop gnidart deifitrof a ta devirra ehS
?aedi doog a saw pirt diputs siht taht thguoht reve ehs dah yhW
,reh tsniaga nrut esrevinu elohw eht teL
,eriw ecnef eht htiw dedilloc dah tohs reH .dednuofbmud
.ti otni depmuls dna
,gnillewd s’retsam-kcod eht fo aera ni-decnef eht ediseb saw ehS
.tnaem ti tahw sseug ot ti daer ot elba eb ot deen t’ndid ehs
.nug-ria reh debbarg ehS
,sgar erabdaerht ni desserd erew meht fo llA
.ytefas eht derebmemer xof eht woN
fo strap lanif dna
,noitsuahxe reh htiw delgnim nehw
,oot ,ti nettog evah thgim dna
.doolb reh htiw wena meht etirw dna sdrow eht rettahs dluow ehs
.nopaew sih htiw ecitcarp on ot elttil dah wollef siht tnaem sdnuor fo yticracs eht taht
,peels lufssilb a otni
reilrae setunim owt ylnO
.sevaw fo gnihsarc eht saw ereht
,yawa htgnel s’mra na saw dels reH
,reh ta derats eH
.ecno ta tpmetta eht denodnaba ehs taht ereves os niap fo noisolpxe eht dnuof dna ti evom ot deirt ehS
,tsaoc eht gnola erehwyreve erew yehT
.eulb eht otni yaw reh no gnitaolf saw ehs hcihw hguorht duolc a ylno saw tsim eht dna
.enilcni eht sdrawot ti dehcram ehs sa wons eht ni sworruf gniggid stoob reh
,yenmihc s’retsam-kcod eht morf ekoms fo kcal eht deciton evah thgim ehs ,esiwrehtO
.emit doog edam ehs fi drayparcs eht morf klaw ’syad owt ylno erew hcihw ,skcod eht ot teg ot
,odavarb reh lla roF
,detnap ehs sa dniheb rehtruf-reve llef eh
,nettogrof dels reh fo thgiew emosnedrub eht
,reh otni nettog dah dloc eht rof ,derevihs ehS
tlob eht no kcab krej ot neht dna
,taorht reh dnuora sdnah sih depparw
.moc tod nozamA retsnom etaroproc morf elbaliava si
.od ot tnaem yeht tahw ees ot dnuora tiaw t’ndid ehs
.meht hsurb sreksihw reh tlef ehs
.yraew dna hguor enot sih
.sddo eht nmad dna
.dnuora kool suoituac a dah dna seenk reh otno flesreh deggard ehs
erom desaercni dna
dehgual ehs dna ,remmus sa mraw sa saw ti tsal ta litnu
.sgniw nworg dah ehs fi sa saw ti tub
,tnecsed reh lortnoc ot tpmetta elituf a ni rehto eht ro yaw eno denael ehS
.gnitoohs os did eh
.meht ta ti delevel ehs nehw deppots yehT
,ebirt lerriuqs eht fo eutriv dna kramllah a
,derahs slamina rehto ynam os hcihw
.tug eht ot kcik a ekil revo reh gnilbuod
”.mraw em peek nac uoY“
,ti fo kcohs eht ni dna
.elbuort sih rof ruf etihw fo lluf-tsif a ylno htiw ttub sih no kcab llef tub ,reilrae dnoces-tilps a neeb eh dah
.ti esu ot hcihw htiw ria elttil yrev dah ehs
ralloc reh otni demmals tellub driht siH
,dias xof eht nehw saw tahT
.doolb ym fo tser eht eb dluow tahT
,dnuorg eht tih ehs nehw
,od ot tuo tes dah ehs tahw
”tsiM eht ni reviR ehT“
2 fo 2 traP ,elawD yb
,denrut dah ehs fI ”!hctib ,yeH“
.esiwrehto neeb ti dah neve ti etarepo ot dnah eerf a evah t’ndid ehs tub
,denraw ehs ”,kcab yatS“
?enog erew ehs fi mih fo erac ekat dluow ohw dnA
.ylimaf sih htiw yawa mih dellac dah ecnahc fo tsiwt emos ,ycnegreme emoS .ereht t’nsaw eH
.detnuat enirevlow eht
,slirtson gnirettulf hguorht peed gnihtaerB
tfel gnihton saw ereht litnu
,tsehc reh no mra gnilbmert sih yal eH
,eson eht no hsulf reh dekcams hcnarb a
,mra doog gniniamer reh htiw ,dna
:nwo sih sa emit emas eht ta ffo tnew tohs txen reH
,bmilc ot deunitnoc nus eht sa
,nrut eht koot ehs sA
.yas enirevlow eht draeh ehs
.ylsseldrow gnivom htuom
llih tsal eno bmilc ot tub dah ehs
,reh hsurc ro ezispac ot nrut yreve ta gninetaerht
.ssot-remmah cipmylO eht fo rennam eht ni
,dnuorg eht tih eh erofeb daed ,despalloc eH
,sseniraw lacipyt reh taht
,seert eht hguorht reh ta tuo gnireep seye eht
,thguoht ehs ,owt naht eroM
,ruof eht fo aremihc tsegral eht ,flow a
.sgnilpas sa niht dna deye-neknus
.dias eciov elbisivni eht
.dekaorc ehS ”?woH“ .syad ni tpels t’ndah eh evitisop saw ehs taht
,retsam-kcod eht morf dia gniggeb no tnetni
ylpeets os ffo pord dluow
pu reh depleh eH
,retal sdnoces wef a nrut emas eht koot stidnab eht nehW
.retrats eht desserp ehs
ezingocer dluoc ehs erus saw ehs enoemos
.sthgieh eht morf nwod tpews taht
…raey fo emit siht etarepsed teg yehT
,ti otni thgiew elohw reh denael dna
.pohs eht dnuora gniyl dah d’ehs eno ylno eht saw ti tub
,noitpecrep reh fo segnirf eht ta yawa eta
,enilretaw eht evoba htdaerb s’dnah a
”,asuL ,peels tonnac uoY“
”.em ekil tsuj kool ll’uoY“
.esae htiw lluks s’nam a otni hsams dluoc ti neht
.wol saw ytidimuh eht nehw eb ot dednet yeht sa
.roolf yrd a dna gninrub erif a eb dluow ereht erehw
”!yap annog er’uoY ?em raeh uoY“
.setteuohlis tniaf erew
noonretfa etal saw ti
.eonac reh dna asuL rof thgir gnimia
degnevacs d’ehs sesnel eht mih evig ot
,reilrae morf no dehctiws llits ,thgis resal eht thguorb ehS
,ezis emas eht fo mraerif a naht ygrene elzzum ssel raf dah nopaew reh taht eurt saw ti elihw tuB
,egalliv reh fo worht s’enots a nihtiw ot
tsim etihw ekil diov A
.edalb reh dehtaehs-er dna
.tohs rewop-lluf erom eno rof hguone ylno saw ereht
,eci eht htiw snoisilloc gnidiova fo dohtem tseb eht
;dedilloc staob rieht erofeb tnatsni na
seirettab rieht gnisu erew yeht dna ehs
.nwod gniyal fo ecnegludni eht flesreh timrep ehs did gof eht otni deraeppasid dah ti nehw ylnO
,semilc krats eseht ni tneps neeb dah efil reh fo elohw eht rof
.deliaw ehs sa ecaf reh ot gnizeerf tons dna sraet reh
.tnemeticxe reh htaenrednu deirub saw
,tsehc reh hguorht detaidar niaP
,ikiM raed reh ot kcab
.reh llik ot gniyrt llits erew yeht dna
,noitsuahxe htiw hsigguls sbmiL
.sreusrup reh ot noitaler ni saw ehs erehw fo erus reven saw ehs os
,revir yrev siht fo htuom eht morf raf ton
taob rehto eht otni dehcnup ti erehw
.ees dluoc reh gnisahc raguoc dlo eht neve fi detbuod ehs taht etelpmoc os saw ssenkrad eht hguoht
.reh dnuora lla mraw gnihtemos saw erehT
liat reh morf ruf fo lufdnah a dehctans dah xof eht erehw ecalp eht deciton ehs ,os gniod nI
,reh ta dehgual yehT ”!ti naem I“
?niaga mih ees reve ehs dluoW
:dedda eh ,gnisaet ,nehT
.tbed rieht gniraelc fo sepoh ni yenruoj reh no tuo tes dna
ria reh fo dne eht depsarg dah ehs toof rehto eht htiW
,eguag erusserp eht tcepsni ot edis sti no nug-ria eht denrut ehs
”?sesnel eht dnif uoy diD“ ”?seY“ ”!ikiM“
,dednetxe smra reh htiw dnuora ti gnuws dna dne eno yb ti dezies ehS
,xof eht tub ,esacriats a detnuom evah thgim ehs esae emas eht htiw ecnef eht pu delbmarcs ehs ;sdnah htiw hguoht sa knil-
.reggirt eht dellup dna
.ytivac lainarc sih no ni
.nwo reh fo smelborp nopaew dah
daeha knab eht no ereht dnA
,reh no raeb ot ti gnirb dluoc eh erofeb
”!yawa gnitteg s’ehs ,ti oD
.reveostahw msinahcem gnireets on dah dna
.nus eht htiw pu gnimoc saw gnirps
,wol ti tnes dna tohs reh deliops ti taht
,dnuorg eht otno ,gnimaets
,lamina laref a ekil delworg eH
.sucof reraelc otni emac seiromem eht sa denworf ehS
.uoy sa ytterp sa eb reven ll’I“
,edils ytsur a htiw eceip dlo derettab a ,lotsip sih rof tnew eh
,tsrow sti od mrots eht teL
.ylkaew ti depsalc ehs
,ikiM ot teg ot tsael ta dah ehs
.ssim yldrah dluoc eh taht egnar esolc hcus ta tub ,gnimia neve ton
”!tihS“ .kcilc ,kcilC
.ytiniffAruF no seirots sti fo erom dnif nac uoY
elims a derahs yehT
,gnitoohs deppots eH
.ria-dim syaw detrap dels reh dna ehs
gnituohs ehT .reh dehsurc evah llew thgim ti
.ti eveileb t’ndluoc ehs ,tsrif tA
.tsrif-eson dnuorg eht kcurts dah ti erehw nwod-edispu
.enilretaw eht woleb tsuj
,tsim nedlog hguorht
.epoh dna seye reh tuhs naht
.sdnoces ni reh no eb dluow stidnab ehT
,traeh eht ni thgir ,emit siht eurt mih gnikirts sreh
,seye reh denepo asuL nehW
.niats a ekil htrae eht denekrad ti sa tsorf gnitlem
hcnarb eht desaeler asuL
.sevlow delir ekil lwoh ot detrats dniw eht dna
”?nug-pop elttil ruoy tfil t’naC“
.ti desu ehs nehw nwod regnulp eht ecrof ot thgiew ydob reh fo elohw eht koot ti tub
?pirt siht gnikam no detsisni ehs dah yhW
.hsif ot tuo eno elttil sih koot nisuoc yM“
;dnoces a sretem derdnuh owt ta evom ot elitcejorp marg eno-ytnewt a teg ot ria dezirusserp fo tol a sekat tI
.ecalp ni eonac reh rohcna ot ti gnisu saw dna
.ecnausrup esolc ni tfarc rehto eht htiw
,neddus a fo sselthgieW
,wons eht hguorht pu dehsup sdeer neerg dna ssarg tuB
.reh dednimer dneirf elbisivni reh
sthguoht reh ni ehs saw desaelp oS
.knard ehs elihw daeh reh deldarc dna
tnurg laitseb a htiw dna sniev reh ni toh saw enilanerda eht tub
sgniraeb llab retemillim-neetneves derif ti
.detsuahxe dna gnideelb llits saw ehs dna
,gniraeh reh fo egde tsehtruf eht nO
.decnartne saw ehs elihw esolc tperc gnivah
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.retaw emos uoy teg ll’I
.denedaed dna kcals llef
eguag erusserp taerg gnippohw a saw nug eht fo edis thgir eht nO
,krims tnahpmuirt ,cinam a htiw ,neht
.yenoh sa wolley dna kciht sa
.lla retfa esahc evig ot tnaem yeht ,oS
emit tsrif eht rof was ehs erehw
.lluh latem s’eonac eht tsniaga gnignab drah gnihtemos fo dnuos eht rof ton ti erew
,mra eno htiw od ton dluoc ehs gnihtemos ton saw tahT
.enola eid dna aes ot tuo tfird ot ylno
,srotom rieht yolpme ot dah yeht taht sdneb thgit no ylfeihc saw tI
.elpmis os lla saw tI
,won enog saw enilanerda ehT
.stohs rewop-lluf erom owt rof ria hguone saw erehT .desruc dna
:deeps ta gnola deyevnoc gnieb osla elihw retaw eht no debbob tegrat dna retoohs htob elihw enola tel
.tsaerb eht evoba tsuj
,degrahc saw yrettab eht taht gniyarP
knaht ,hO“ .kcolc lacinahcem a fo gnikcit tfos eht dna lio-
,neeb dah epols rehto eht naht noitategev fo resraps
.gnixaoc emos eriuqer ot gniog saw sihT
,yaw siht lla emoc evah ot ,ytip A
mra rehto reh evom ot tnew ehs litnu
,reh fo retnec eht sdrawot dewang ssenetihw eht ,erom dna eroM
.remmus naht retaerg erusaelp a saw mih fo llems eht dna
.traeh sih fo driht reppu eht derettalps dna mih otni dehcnup tohs reh dna pihw-
.sreh otni derats seye tohsdoolb ,dezarC
***   ”.eid lliw uoy neht
did ehs litnu yks eht otni yenruoj taht ekat ton dluow ehS
.tnerruc eht tsniaga ,llihpu dna maertspu htob gnitaolf saw ehs dnif ot
”.eid lliw I neht ,peels I fI“
.hteet nwo reh wenk ehs naht ycamitni ssel on htiw lavivrus fo sralucitrap eht wenk ehs dna
sthguoht reh ni decafrus ecaf s’ikiM
,ffo tfel ew nehW
.deneppah gnihtoN
,meht fo eerht was ehs
.taob a dnuora yawa reh wenk ehs tey
”EGRAHC WOL :GNINRAW“ dehsalf yalpsid eht
.esolc erew yeht taht nwonk dna nwo reh ton
esolc os dessap taht srulb krad
,noisiv thgin fo kcal ’slerriuqs eht detnemal ehS
,edir eht rof gnola htaed dna
,srettel hsilgnE otni detaretilsnart
.denruter ehs nehw stbed reh raelc llits dna
.taeh ydob gniniamer reh pas ot retniw htiw gnidulloc
.ti dehcterts ehs fi syad wef a rof hguone
.taht ta hgual ot dah ehS
,hcnarb gnidurtorp emas eht fo lluf-ecaf a tog
dnabsuh reh ot lleweraf dib ebirt lerriuqS eht fo asuL ,emit tsaL
.thgir sih no raguoc denob-war ,gniyerg a dna
tnecs elbategev knad ,tniaf eht fo enon dah dna yrd saw hcihw
nehctik eht otni tuo deleehw eH
,sevaw naeco eht sdrawot gnivom neeb dah ehs erofeb erehW
.evivrus ot snoitar dna tnet a naht erom dedeen ehs tros a fo saw
,maertspu ,meht evoba raf
,nomlas eht dna rahc eht htiw
,hcuot tsethgils eht ta tsrub thgim taht elbbub paos a erew ehs hguoht sa ,yltneg
.sgniht denmad eht worht ot llew sa tsuj od dluow ehs taht
,detrevni elims eht neht tuB
,on tub ,esaercni na neeb evah dluow ereht fi sa nug-
nettogrof sreusrup reh
sknab eht gnola seert eht fo seldeen eht dna
,ekacdees dna nacimmep emos dna
gniraeb llab ehT
,gnitnap ,eenk eno otno nwod tnew dna
.etarucca devorp rehtaew eht rof esnes reH
.emoh tsomla saw ehs ngis a dna
,eliforp gnidnecsed sti fo gard desaercni eht yb dewolS
,ti fo tuo deppans ehS
swodahs rieht dna yad eht neewteb noitanretla eht ,deeps hcus tA
sbmil gnilgnad hcus ynam eht fo eno fo dloh thguac dah
rewop eht gniwohs
tutitkunI saw tI
,gnittes nus eht htiw
,owt rehto eht naht retrohs ,tsomreppu ehT
.emit tsrif eht rof evol edam dah ikiM dna ehs erehw revir eht fo htuom eht ediseb hcaeb elttil eht yb ssap dluow ehs tnemom a nI .emoh saw ehS
,retaw eht otni ti dehsup
.reh raen erehwon tih ot ediw raf tnew srehto eht
,lla ti fo yrolg eht yb dexifsnart ,dehctaw ehS
.oot ,won pu gnimraw saw tI
pu tis ot deirt ehS .won kcab saw eH
erom gnihton od dluoc dna ti tih ot gniog saw ehs wenk ehs
,did ehs gniht tsal eht saw ti fi nevE
,won dertah htiw dliw saw eh
.dnilb tsomla ni enog dah ehs
gnihtaerb reh fo dnuos eht hguorht ,revir eht dna
.ton did ehs hcihw
.won reh nopu tsomla saw eH
.lerrab eht saw ebut lartnec eht elihw
,reh fo pot no thgir osrot sih gniggard
.smra s’ikiM fo htmraw eht leef dna
.elbissop sa hcum sa wolf eht htiw evom dna
.revir gnizeerf eht otni nwod ti derewol dna
.reggirt eht no saw dnah lanoitcnuf gniniamer reh dna
,sesnel fo egakcap eht dessot dah ehs hcihw otni tfird eht dnuof gnivah ,nehT
,ecnedive eht gnihgiew ,ereht doots ehS
did lerrab eht ot detnuom retniop resal A
.tegrat ffo reev ti ekam dna
;htgnerts rieht evresnoc ot ylgniraps
,htaerb reh thguac ehs ecnO
”,llew did uoY“ ”?llew od I diD“
.dekaos kcab emac sregnif reH
doolb fo tnecs eht thguac dah ehs eciwT
.revoc rieht morf gnigreme serugif eht no dnuora delrihw ehs sa
,tleb sih elkcubnu ot devom dnah s’flow ehT
,tniop eht robaleb ot derit oot ,denway ikiM
aes nrehtuos eht morf ria fo ssam A
.ytluciffid htiw dna kciht tuo emac eman ehT ”?ikiM“ ”!doG
.skcod eht ot klaw s’yad a naht ssel saw ehs nehw
.tser ot tup erew stbuod esoht won tub
,neht tub ,ti fo drow a daer t’ndluoc ehs dna
.reh kootrevo ti erofeb noitanitsed reh hcaer
.nwolf evah dluoc ehs taht thgil os saw traeh reh dna
.esle enoyna eb ot ti rof ralugnis oot erew sracs eht tub ,yrrulb
.thgis a rof ytud
tsop gnidart eht fo evael reh ekat ot dedneterp dah ehs sruoh nwad-erp eht ni tub
.noinapmoc elbisivni na yb denioj neeb dah ehs hguoht sa saw tI
:deniamer pets erom enO
,elbatupsidni saw gnimoc saw mrots a tahT
;derettacs stidnab gniniamer eerht ehT ”!tihs yloH“
.dnuow hself a naht truh erom on meht od dluoc ecived a hcus gnikniht spahrep dna
deciton ehs dah rehtieN
efil nugeb dah reggirt ehT
.dezilaer ehs ,tae oT
,rehtegot tup ti fo tser eht naht erom reh desserped tops dlab taht
.sredluohs reh morf nellaf dah nrecnoc fo thgiew ehT
”tsiM eht ni reviR ehT“
,yawa gnivom saw ehs won
.reggirt eht dellup dna
,nrut yreve ta elcatsbo wen a decaf ehs ekil saw tI
iw yalp annaw tsuj eW“
.dluoc ehs revetahw secnahc reh fo ekam ot deidaer dna
.xat rieht yap naht rehtar
.thguoht ehs ,sey ,hA
.tsal ta tuo nur dah kcul reh demees ti
”tsiM eht ni reviR ehT“   :yojne esaelP
.gnihton naht retteb saw taht ,lleW
.niaga ffo deppot eb ot dedeen riovreser eht erofeb semit evif siht od dluoc ecived reh
.nrut reh saw ti woN
,lotsip deppord eht barg ot gnireets tfel dah enirevlow ehT
.thguoht ni tink sworb htiw
tiaw dna pots ot htaol saw ehs ,llitS
…meht revo lla skram etib htiw senob fo tip a
daeherof reh tsniaga lotsip eht tup eH
.daeh s’xof eht ta lerrab eht delgna dna
.ti htiw emoc ton dah gnirps eht tub ,pu saw nus ehT
tsop gnidart eht fo tuo ti elggums ot gnidnetni
edis reh no ecalp gnitser sti ot nruter nug-ria eht tel ehS
.slaitini rieht devrac dah ikiM dna ehs hcihw otno
htoB	       .niaga deirt t’ndah ehS
mra sselesu eno htiw
tsim a demrof ti
,nepo dna ediw daerps senocenip tessur
,dah ehs yaw eht nellaf ton dah ehs fI
seno gnivil owt eht
.srae reh htiw tuo gnileef ta trepxe emoceb
,ot dah ehs fi occabot reh fo niarg tsal yreve htiw trap ot droffa dluoc ehs
”,em tuoba yrrow t’noD“
,reh ot ekops eciov a nehw saw tahT
.doog emos reh od dluow tI
.elbisiv ylecracs erew sknurt eht taht
,ssenkaew reh fo tnetxe eht ta desirprus saw dna
.tops dlab gnibborht dna war a htiw reh tfel dna pit-
.ti fo dioved morf raf tub
,nopaew sih pu kcip ot troffe na edam dna ,ediw seye
demees ti taht prahs dna raelc os
,teef reh yb devres retteb eb thgim ehs fi cinap a ni derednow dna
,skcor fo lluf dna yllih llits saw dnuorg ehT
smrots elbatciderpnu eht ni thguac teg ot sniatnuom eht ot hguone esolc saw ehs
,emoclew ni reh ot gnivaw enoemos saw
,ecno ,deirt dah ehS
,kcab reh no gniyal ,lerriuqs ehT
.erans latem a ekil
”.tuo skcilk ruof tuoba eonac ruoy otni dehsarc tsomlA
,pals a saw erehT
,lacitcarp eb ot gib oot raf saw hcihw
ehS	       .kram sti dnuof hcihw eno eht raeh reven thgim ehs
.esolc siht saw ehs nehw ton
,dlihc a ekil tpew ehs
taht ti htiw ykcits os won saw akrap reh
.emoh tnerruc eht edir dna
,dnah ni nug ,raguoc eht dna
,os od ot hcihw no mroftalp elbats a dah ehs fi neve
,flesreh dlot ehs ,riapsed reh otni evig ton tsum ehS
egalliv eht ni esoht erew erehT
,nelots dna dnuof eb dluow erusaert reh taht ro ,derevocsid eb dluow yolp reh taht gnitterf tneps eno
.eci fo lluf revir a dna kcab rieht ta mrots a htiw
.nori netlom sa toh dna thgirb
,raeb ot nug-ria reh gnirb ot deniarts ehS
.enizagam eht saw
”.won peels ot thgirla s’tI“
revo nworg llonk a dnuora
eonac reh ni eloh a dehcnup tellub eno
.erofeb naht os ssel tub
,ton dluoc mra tfel deniur reh sa nug-
.gel reh htiw trapa staob rieht devohs dna
.noivilbo otni nwod reh llup esiwrehto ro nword ot
thgirpu delggirw ehS
.mih tog ehs erofeb reh teg ot citnarf
,serawanu reh hctac ot erew drazzilb a fi ydrapoej llams on ni eb dluow ehS
.daeherof s’flow eht no tod der eht gniniart
,noiger larotcep tfel eht ni reh thguac sih elihw
.dloc detsalb eht fo tuo eb dluow ehs ,nooS
reh ta ti detniop ,werd
DNE ***    .kcul eht lla evah tsuj
.sreh ekat ot tnetnoc eb dluow eh neht
,delwarc dna sreh edisgnola taob sih tog eH
,dehsug diulf lanipsorberec dna doolb fo erutxim A
dels reh fo enil eht pu dehctans ehS
,ytefas eht ffo hctiws ot nettogrof dah eH
***   .enog saw ehs dna
,gnihton naht retteb saw tohs kaew a gnikniht
,eonac eht otno yawflah ,ylikahs
”,tar-eert ,rettam eht s’tahW“
,eolf eht hguorht yaw reh dedaerht dna elttorht eht pu denepo ehs
,duola dias ehs ”,wonk I“
.spil sih no llits elims a
...resolc elttil a teg dluoc ehs ylno fi
laes gninrub fo tnecs eht saw erehT
peelsa nellaf evah yllaer thgim ehs dna
keehc reh dezarg rehtona
,ytissecen hguorht ,dah ehs sdneb
,tfel sih no enirevlow a dna xof etihw a yb deknalf ,reh tseraen saw
tod resal a dnif ot nwod dekool eH
,diarfa tey t’nsaw ehs neht neve tuB
,reh retfa emoc ot sa hsiloof os eb t’ndluow stidnab eht
,desaercni deeps eht tub
,seert aktoon dellac elpoep reh tahw htiw
,kcab worg reven thgim ruf eht taht thguoht eht dna
,enod dah ehs sa ecnef eht elacs ot tpmetta naht rehtaR
,kcahs s’retsam-kcod eht ta nwod gnikool eb dluow ehs dna
,nwod thgiarts toohs ylbailer ton dluoc ti ,siht fo esuaceB
,ti htiw emac gninraey lufterger fo gnap a dna ,aes eht fo shtped eht morf hguoht sa
,esirnus litnu gnitsal detbuod dah ehS
,riovreser ria eht saw tsomrewol eht
,dewols dah ssol doolb ehT
esuaceb yrd ton dluoc taht ssenpmad a yb niks eht ot deppos ,derevihs ehS
.taob rieht fo roolf eht otno dekcalc dna
,worra na ekil maertsnwod yawa tohs eonac eht
.teb I ,ytsrihT“ .dekaorc ehs
,ecaf reh yb dehsoows sknurt-eerT
.nwo reh no saw ehS
,tniop taht dnoyeb erif ot eunitnoc dluoc ehS
,llih eht fo edis drawdniw eht saw sihT
,efil ot derekcilf neercs DCL nA
.cra wollahs a ni drawrof reh depmar
,eromyna doog on saw taob sih fI
,omma fo ytnelp dah ehs elihw ,oS
ees dluoc ehs lla nehw neve ti wenk dna yromem reh otni tops eht denrub dah ehs ,tuB
,kcap reh ni dedlof tnet a saw erehT
.wons eht otni tsrif-ecaf detlit neht
eonac eht fo egde eht no tnemamra reh decarb ehS
dels reh dniheb tog ehs
,tiusrup fo niatrec dna tsaf gnikniht ,pot eht ta ecnO
thgir eht ot tneb revir eht ,daeha pU
,thgirpu srae trohs reh thguorb tahT
”.hguot m’I“ .dias eh
,yad dnoces eht fo gninrom eht litnu noisulli yppah taht ni evil ot elba saw ehS
,pmal s’renim reh esu ot
.raeb dluoc ehs naht erom saw
.lavirra reh etarbelec ot ittefnoc neeb evah llew sa yam reh tuoba gnillaf wons eht elihw
.taoc dedeennu na ffo nworht evah thgim nam a sa ylidaer sa snedrub enillatsyrc rieht dehs
.hguone saw ti tub
,edecer ot nageb mra dna tsehc reh ni niap gnigrus eht dna
,yawa sretem wef a ylno morf slotsip gnitniop raguoc dna enirevlow eht nees evah dluow ehs
,ti evael t’ndluoc ehs
sraet htiw dellif seye reH
,deniamer llits sduolc eht tub
,taef a hcus fo elbapac flesreh deveileb evah ton dluow ehs dna
.htmraw reh evresnoc ot sgel reh revo liat reh depard dna
,aes eht yb egalliv elttil reh ot kcab gniog saw ehS
.gnituohs saw enoemoS
.noitadnuni dednetrop taht
.mra eno htiw dleiw ot yvaeh oot saw nug-ria reh ,taht fo pot nO
niahc eht pirg reh tel stoob ekil-nettim reH
,sepytonehp gnireffid dah lla was ehs nem ruof ehT
.dne reven dluow wenk ehs taht remmus a fo htmraw eht otni
,htgnerts gnidaf reh fo tsal eht htiW
,nihtiw morf emac ti
,deppots yllanif sraet eht nehW
.slirtson reh otni thgiarts doolb dna enob nettor fo knits eht welb
.dnim gninnips reh ot derotser noitautis eht fo ytivarg eht saw
.tnerruc tnelubrut eht ni gnilbmut dna gnibbob
tsae eht ni deraeppa enil mils A
.derif dna ,egacbir sih fo retnec eht ot
revir fo hctap raelc a ni saw ehs litnu tiaw dluoc ehS
kael wen siht gnidrager
elitcejorp reh tcelfed ot hguone neeb dah ecnatsiser eht tub ,hguorht dehcnup dna
tnerruc dna sdniw rettib eht
.eolf eci na otni thgiarts tfarc reh dehcnual dah ehS
.gnidnal reh fo ecrof eht yb dezad
.srettel der thgirb ni
:dels eht ot kcap reh gniruces sepor eht tuc ehs ,tuo efinK
.staob gnihsif fo noitcelloc llams a tpek eh erehw
.ekaw s’mrots eht no ni devom evah tsum
,taht od dluoc ti fI
.omma fo tuo saw eH .kcilC
,nug eht deppord eH
,raey hcae did yeht sa
.llih eht revo gniliart nees evah dluohs ehs hcihw
sehcnarb fo ytisned a hcus htiw sgniht yggahs ,taerg
,drawdnuorg tfird ot nageb sekalfwons tsrif eht dna deid sdniw eht emit eht yB
,thgis eht no nrut ot ytinutroppo eht koot ehS
,retaw gnihsur fo dnuos eht yb erom neve denetfos dna
seiks eht dehctaw ehs sa gnol os
.enola tnecs yb reh kcart ot elba neeb evah dluow stidnab eht erus tlef ehs
.sgnignoleb reh gniggard elihw
.dettimda ehs ”,erew syawla uoY“
.rohtua yrots trohs gninniw-drawa dna
derevocer xof ehT
.taobrotom demottob-talf a otni xof daed eht gnipmud
.denosaer ehs ,sdnoces wef a hctac dna
:reviecer eht morf dednetxe sebut eerhT
,pu kcab emac eh nehw dna
”,sevaeL eht ni nwoD ecaF“ noitcelloc yrteop stI
.mrah reh gniod no reve naht tnetni erom dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,rehto hcae ta dekool dna ereht doots htob yehT
,deneppah dah taht lla htiw nevE
.tfarc gniknis eht ni llits sgel sih
”.hguoht ,ecaf ruoy no racs ytsan a evah annog er’uoY
,senob nekorb dah ehs fi kcehc ot emit gnikat neve tuohtiw doots ehS
,tsehc sih dehctulc eH
.doolb gniliart ,erohs revir eht yb eonac a ot revo kcap reh deluah
.ohcnop reh htiw eson reh debbad ehs sa ytidiputs reh desruc ehS
tniop eht ot reh gniltsoj ,reggirt eht dellup ehs sa tsuj enob-
,dloc llits saw tI
.yrrow t’nod ,meht dnuof eW“
”,edalb-redluohs ruoy fo eceip a ffo deppans
.retaw tlips ekil ecaf sih revo daerps kool desufnoc A
,ecaf sih ni taps ehS
tlob eht no kcab dekrej ehs ,daetsnI
,ecalp s’retsam-kcod eht ta kcab gnizag tuB
,sdrawnwod pit ot nageb eson eht ecnO
tohsdoolb dna yffup os erew seye sih dna ,gniyrc saw eH
”,peels tonnac uoy ,asuL“
”?leef I kniht uoy od lleh eht woH“ ”?leef uoy od woH
.tnemec fo lluf saw ti ekil tlef taorht reH
.reh yebo ton dluow ydob reh tub ,pu tis ot deirt ehs dna taht gnirebmemer
htrae eht morf gnidurtorp toor dekoorc eht was ehs nehW
deb eht fo edis rehto eht ot dnuora deleehw neht
,gnol eht fo selacs eht was ehs ,daehrevo sehcnarb eht nI
,thguoht ehs ,yleruS
,remraw werg ti elihw eht llA
sdrawkcab dereggats eH
,noissessop reh ni ylefas won sesnel eht htiW
.peels fo sdnoces wef a hctans dna
kcab knas ehs sa detcelfer ehs ,elpoep emoS
setunim erom wef A
.thgit gnulc dna egaggab reh pota tpael ehs
,enots tsedrah eht ni reh rof nettirw eb etaf lufitip a teL
;neht reh kootrevo ytip-fles dna terger fo noisluvnoc A
.sdoow eht ni dels reh neddih dna
segadnab dna epat ni pu depparw os redluohs reh dnuof dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,deb nwo reh llems tsomla dluoc ehS
maeb gniliec nedoow a saw was ehs gniht tsrif eht
.emit emos reh thguob dah hctam gnituohs riehT
,dnilb derif dna reh ta nug eht detniop ,ti delggot eH
,sdnoces fo elpuoc a naht erom neeb evah ton dluoc tI
.nosaer etisoppo eht rof tub ,niaga revo gniht emas eht rednow ot nageb ehs litnu
fo trap lanif dna
,dessap dah sruoh ynam woH
,truhnu tub detailimuh
.rebmahc gnirif eht otni llab a dedaol msinahcem eht sa ”knuhc-
,semitefil noillim a ni tae dluoc egalliv reh naht ereh erom tub
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,tuo emac noom eht txen nehW
”.flesruoy emos esu dluoc uoy ekil kool uoY“ .deddon ehS
.ti tsiser ton dluoc ehs dna
,rae tfel s’asuL fo trap ffo koot tellub A
,llih eht fo mottob eht raen
,srotom rieht desu yeht nehw neve tuB
.koobenohp a hguorht hcnup ot yticolev hguone htiw
.neht yb no devom evah dluow mrots ehT
.tnerruc eht htiw detfird ehS
.won syad ruof peelsa neeb ev’uoY“ ”.saw reveN
.rotom reh no yrettab eht kcehc dna daeh reh tfil ot derad ehs
enob dna hself dna ruf gnivac
,neht ,elbatterger saw tI
.kcab mra ruoy fo esu eht teg dluohs uoy si swen doog ehT“ .denialpxe eh
,gninnur enod evah thgim ehs naht retsaf on devom ehs ,tsrif tA
.etanutrof flesreh deredisnoc ehs tub
.hctiws-thgil a sa
,yticapac tnecrep owt ta saw tI
tuo dellor gniraeb-llab leets yvaeh A
,aes eht ediseb egalliv a ni doohnamow ot nworg dah ehS
.dias evah ton dluoc ehs
.kcohs fo ksam a emaceb yrotciv leurc fo ronaemed sih
doog erew sddo neht ,os erew taht fI
;deppots dah stohsnug ehT
,erofeb etunim a ylno esahc eht nodnaba ot detnaw dah eh fI
.wons eht rednu neddih neeb dah hcihw hcnarb a deppans dna