.mih no ni gnisolc eb ot demees ti ,taht dna yaw siht gninael
",revetahw gnihton yletulosbA"
,wonk ot sah eno sgniht derdnuh a era ereht ,sediseB
deeps a htiw swodniw rieht edistuo tsap decar
ecaf nwo sti ecnehw
.era ew erehw wonk yltcaxe t'nod I
,taR eht emitnaeM
,laed taerg a tpels taR eht
.ti od t'nod ylpmis yehT
,taht otni nwod yaw ruo ekam ll'eW
"swolliW eht ni dniW ehT"  fo
;egde tsehtruf sti ot
.dneirf sih fo ngis yna rof edis rehtie no ylsuoixna gnikool
,srood rieht ta gnirettab erew niar dna dniw elihw seloh rieht ni guns ,slamina ysworD
,taR derutan-doog eht dias ",thgir lla ,O"
,edistuo sgnirettap eht dna
.no deggij eh sa
,ylwols ,tsal ta dias eh ",lleW"
.nageb secaf eht nehT
fo III retpahC saw sihT      .dnopser
!yloM ,yloM ,yloM"
,taR retaW eht ot hsiw sih denoitnem eloM eht revenehw tuB
?gnihtyna enoyna gnillet tam-rood a fo draeh reve ohW
desaercni gnirettap ehT
.nigeb ot ydaer saw yalp eht neht
,ylisub gnikrow sgel ruof lla
!swollef fo tseb ehT
.uoy ecudortni ll'I neht dna—
,yllufreehc tuo gnillac emit eht lla dna ,dnuorg elohw eht revo gnikrow ylsuoirobal
.yltneitapmi taR eht deirc
sevael yrd eht otni llew tog eloM eht oS
.gel sih gnisrun llits ,eloM eht
.hpmuirt taerg ni taR eht demialcxe
,krow drah 'setunim net emoS
,no tnew eh ",won lleW"
.dooW dliW eht ot
senal ytsud gnola selbmar eht
,detiripsid ,pu dellup yeht—
"?uoy llet I did tahw ,erehT"
.ti morf uoy peek ot tseb ym did I
;esitcarp uoy skcirt dna segdod dna ,taeper uoy sesrev dna
.eloM eht detseggus
,taR deticxe eht deirc
.snoitpeced dlo eht htiw
;erofeb dna dniheb ni gnirehtag ,yldipar
,tuc eht ta dekool uoy dna
weiv ni lluf doots sruobal rieht fo tluser eht tsal ta llit
,serutacirac delbmeser spmuts no sesugnuf
',woN' .dekil uoy gnihtyna dnif dluoc uoy eveileb I
.kool doog a dah dna
tsal ta enuJ taht
.dedneffo eb ot erus eb d'eh
.emit a rof denetsil eH
"?gnihtemos ro rennid—
pu deppirt eloM eht ylneddus nehw
.ykcommuh dna ypmuh dna yllih lla smees dnuorg eht erehw ,su fo tnorf ni ereh nwod lled
deksa "?yttaR ,dnuof uoy evah tahW"
?klat dna thgin lla wons eht no tis ot gniog er'uoy esoppus I" ,yldniknu rehtar
".ffo eb tsum yllaer ew neht dna
,eloM eht dnuof eh ereht dna
ecnatniauqca eht ekam ot detnaw gnol dah eloM EHT
,aes ta ylsselepoh dna ,yraew
,htworgrednu neerg ni peed
bew eht no seirots erom ynam dnif nac uoY
ton wenk eh ,ylsselmia
hguorht wap a teg dluoc eh llit dekrow eH
.gep demotsucca sti morf gnissim saw pac s'eloM ehT
,drah dna tes ecaf sih
,tsap dehsad ti sa mih dehsurb tsomla lamina eht ,daetsnI
.thgir lla yllareneg er'ew neht
dlog saw yerg dna
,nekraeh ot llits doots eh sA
.semit fo stol ,erofeb gniht fo tros emas eht neeS
;wohyna ,won krad hctip ylraen ytterp s'tI .yawa tser"
,dna eganosrep tnatropmi na hcus eb ot ,stnuocca lla yb ,demees eH .regdaB eht fo
,dnats-allerbmu eht yb yal syawla hcihw ,sehsolog siH
.eloh a morf mih ta tuo gnikool ,ecaf depahs-egdew live elttil a
,rewsna on gniviecer ,dna ,semit lareves "!yloM"
ylnedduS  "!taR ,no emoc ,O"
yrteop delbbircs semitemos eh yad trohs sih gniruD
.ylbaresim eloM eht dias ",pmuts a ro hcnarb neddih a revo deppirt evah tsum I"
.etal gnisir dna ylrae gniriter
.wons eht ni gij elbeef a gnitucexe ot llef dna "!yar-oo-
,sngis dna ,sdrowssap naem I
tsal ta nehw ,erom ro ruoh na rof
raeh yltniaf dluoc yeht
,daehrevo yks yleets drah a htiw noonretfa llits dloc a saw tI  .regdaB .rM htiw
;tsael ta selpuoc ni emoc ew ,emoc ot evah ew fI
noitarolpxe rof senim suoiretsym neeb dah hcihw ,secalp neddih lla dna seirrauq ,slled ,sespoC
,erofeb sa edareuqsam hcir ni toir dluoc yeht llit
.gnitaralihxe neve —gnireehc tey dna
.prahs dna hserf erew selos rieht no selpmip eht dna
,noonretfa eno os dna
,wenk eno dna ,egats eht no yletaciled deppets esor-god gniyaled dna tnediffid eht
,thguoht eh ,sknab eht ni seloh eht morf yawa teg ylno dluoc eh fI  .prahs dna live dna deye-
,ruodra htiw meht ediseb knab-wons a dekcatta taR ehT
,elttil a ylniatrec !sey—!on—!sey—
.elbuort ni flesruoy dnif ll'uoy ro
,no mih del tI .gniticxe dna
.tfel thgil elttil a llits s'ereht elihw emoh rof trats a ekam dna rehtegot sevlesruo llup tsum yllaer ew"
".wonk uoy ,thgir lla saw dooW dliW eht em dlot uoY" .eloM eht dias
,sesrev sih rof roolf eht ot nwod dehcaer eh
,yllacitehtap sterces rieht dna sevlesmeht desopxe won ,remmus yfael ni
",seod eh gnisoppus ,lleW"
,dnuorg eht ffo llew teef htob
,elihwa derednop eH "!ynnuF
ssenkrad gnirehtag eht hguorht yaw sih edam eh
",tsaeb dedaeh-kciht uoy—
remmus tsap eht no seton gnirapmoc dna gnillet-yrots fo laed doog a saw ereht yltneuqesnoc dna
retal owt ro ruoh nA
,rettO ro regdaB erew uoy fi esruoc fO
,wen erew sehsolog ehT
erutnevda ,trofmoc ,evol fo
,ylsuoixna denetsil eh sa retrauq yreve morf llit ,deilpitlum ti dna
.hguone thgir ti ees I"
,kcab htgnerts ym teg dna ,regnol elihw a ereh tser em tel tsum uoY
,htrae fo noitamrofsnart tnaidar eht dna
;sessarg gnidees fo yalp eht dna
.yldnik taR eht dias "!eloM dlo rooP"
,thgin-ot mraw dna yrd peels ot tnaw uoy fi ,skcommuh eht fo sedis eht no yllaicepse
"swolliW eht ni dniW ehT"
em s'tI ?uoy era erehW
,llirhs dna tniaf yrev llits ,nehT
,rettil citsemod fo eceip rehtona dnuof evah ot mees uoy"
,denethgirf os neeb ev'I" ,deirc eh "!taR O"
".mih dnif uoy nehw tub
.edis rehtie no mih ta shtuom ylgu edam seloh dna
mle dna hceeb fo yrepard ywollib eht ,teskciuq fo sneercs eht
emaharG htenneK yb ,III retpahC
,flesym emoh nwo sih ta mih no llac ot derutnev neve reven ev'I
,shtap lla gnikasrof ,neht
,puorg eht ni ecalp sih ot ylsuoicarg devom
,yhs yrev os s'eH"
.ylevitnetta niaga ti gninimaxe ,taR eht dias
rood a no tis rO ?tam-rood a rednu peels rO ?tamrood a tae ew naC
,eenk sih morf deppils
".rettam rehtona etiuq eb dluow ti
rehto hcae ot no gnidloh
htap eht ffo gnuws eH
pu gnignirps
nosrep luftegrof dna sselerac yrev emos taht snaem ylpmis tI"
serutnevda ynam os dna ,dednuor
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.hguorht edaw ot su rof peed oot eb noos lliw wons eht dna
deraeppasid dna pmuts a dnuor gnuws eh sa
.tam-rood ruoy dnuof uoy esruoc fo dnA
,si ti fo tsrow ehT
flesmih dnuof syawla eh
"?eh dluow ,flesmih yb ereh gnimoc dnim t'ndluow daoT .rM evarb eht yleruS"
.dehsinav dah gniht eht
,tif t'ndluow taht semyhr revo gniyrt dna
;yawa tseb demees
,ereh deretnuocne dah woregdeh dna dleif ni srellewd elttil rehto
.llew os mih wonk I hguoht
,flesmih ot ylteiuq gniyas mih draeh eloM eht nehT
detlah eh sA .kcab og ot tnaw dna etatiseh mih edam dna
",ereh kooL" .deredisnoc dna
wons a eb ot demees dah tahw fo
,teef sih rednu delkcarc sgiwT
.weiv ot desopxe yal tam-rood ybbahs yrev a dna
,nosaer rehto yna rof naht taR eht egilbo ot erom
"!t'nod I fi ees ,rehto ro ydobemos ot—
,retlehs dereffo hcihw
retpahc driht eht si yrots s’yadot
flesmih yb tuo og ot noituloser eht demrof eh
.evol dna efil ot kcab remmus gnipeels eht ssik ot saw taht ecnirp eht
;selbmut htiw desiurb dna eugitaf htiw
,detarocednu yrtnuoc eht dekil eh taht dalg saw eH
,neeb dah ti retpahc hcir a hcuS
was ro ,meht deteerg yltnelis dna ylmirg taht
.lla ta tros taht ton era yehT
,esuoh eht deretne-er eh nehT
ot ti tuoba nialpmoc dna og llahs I emoh teg I nehW
.nageb gniltsihw eht nehT
rooD' ,flesti ot dias dnim citsejam ruoy ecno ta dna
.woleb morf emoc ot demees taht
;enil eht ni ecalp sti ekat ot htrof tperc
;sdleifnroc wolley hguorht dna
",gnol yrev ereh tis t'nac eW"  .tuo yaw on
",lla ta taht ekil t'ndluow eh erus m'I ,O"
.mih dnuora snoitcerid lla ni ylf wons eht edam dna
,emalf fo trups a pu tnes dna delkcarc erif eht
",snaem ti tahw ees I esruoc fO"
,esuoh eht tfel taR ehT  .enog osla erew
.tuo daeh sih tup dna taerter rieht fo ecnartne eht ot tnew eH
".ylteiuq tiaw ll'uoy fi ,yad emos gnola gnimoc eb ll'eh dna
.retaw-doolf ekil yawa gniniard eb ot demees thgil eht dna
thgilnoom fo dia eht yb daer dluoc yeht
,ti hguorht sgel elttil rieht gard yldrah dluoc yeht taht peed os gnitteg saw wons eht
.uoy ton tub ;deifsitas etiuq neeb evah dluow elpoep emoS .oN
.timil tsehtraf sti ot
ssenekil rieht yb tnemom eht rof mih deltrats dna
tcerid gnidael
.pots tsum siht" ,yrgna
.ecalp eht tuoba ydobyreve yb tlef ecneulfni neesnu sih ekam ot
,yltneserp taR eht dias ",neht woN"
,ti no wons eht revo emoh egdels dna tam-
.skcart s'eloM eht dnif ot gnipoh
.taeb daed ytterp su fo htob
,oot nur ot nageb eh ,cinap nI ?ydobemos—
".gniht fo tros taht lla dna ,rennid dna ,snoitativni dna
tops eht ot pu delbboh eloM ehT
"?gnihtyna uoy llet t'nseod tam-rood siht taht"
,ereht ees uoy llup-lleb taht ot no gnah dna ecno ta pu teG
.ni gnisolc saw thgin eht dna
,ti otni slotsip fo ecarb a devohs
htaerb rieht revocer ot knurt-eert nellaf a no nwod tas dna
.swollef su gnoma ,ereh detsaw ylpmis er'uoY
.mih dnuora daerps teprac-fael yrd eht no
.em ot srucco tahw si siht" ,no tnew eh
.ti ot dne on ylpmis eb dluow ereht ro ,sgniht gninigami nigeb ot ton
.ti llac I ,mih fo sselthguoht yreV
,gninetaerht dna wol
si—ereh !olluh !olluH"
er'ew rof ,niaga yrt ew erofeb tser doog a evah ll'ew ereht dna
.wons gnilrihw eht dna dniw neek eht morf noitcetorp a dna
,peels otni ffo deppord yltneserp dna
.neerg krad a detniap
.eloM eht deriuqni
"!yarooH" deirc taR eht
,gnola emac reven regdaB eht tuB
.llits yrev saw lla dna
;hguorht tew tog dna seloh lareves otni nellaf dah yeht
od dna ,ti rof hsup rehtona ekam ot evah llahs eW" .taR eht dias
,gnirettap dna gniltsihw eht dna
,gnilbmert dna gnitnap ereht yal eh sa dnA
dnoces eht dna ,0202 ,ht5 tsuguA no ,goD fO ecioV ehT fo edosipe ht001 eht no deraeppa retpahc tsrif ehT
;detiawa llits saw ynapmoc eht fo rebmem enO .ereh saw
,kool ot seenk sih no nwod gniog ,no tnew eh ",seY
,llup-lleb eht ta pu gnarps eloM eht
;ecaf a was eh thguoht tsrif eh taht ,yltcnitsidni dna
.doow emas eht saw ti taht nwonk evah ton dluow eloM ehT .deedni did tI
,yrtne tsrif sih no ylnialp etiuq draeh dah eh hcihw
,tsal ta gnineve looc ,gnol eht dna
lleb denot-peed a
.8091 ni dehsilbup tsrif
.won llits yrev saw gnihtyrevE
,dum eht ni meht fo stnirpmi eht ees dluoc eH
,llah eht fo renroc a ni doots taht legduc tuots a pu koot
yar-oo-yar-oo-yarooH" neht dna
".dooW dliW eht fo
.srevir-maerd fo sknab tnadrev eht yb derednaw eh dna
,dnuos eht yb flesmih gnidiuG
,niaga meht htiw saw nus eht
.teef hguor yb nopu neddort eb ot etaciled oot dekool taht ,erehwyreve
pu thguac eb ot demees dna ,edis rehtie no tuo ekorb ti noisicedni ni
,redluohs sih revo saw tI
.ereht ton saw eloM eht tuB
elddim yrev eht ni
,knab eht gnola repmacs eht
.ffo yaw gnol yrev a llits
.owt ro etunim a rof thguoht peed ni doots dna
shtap ro ,spag ,sgninepo
,ssel saw thgil eht erehw ot detartenep eh dna
.latem ni gnihtemos fo egde prahs a yb edam saw ti fi sa skooL
;retaw eht fo ecafrus eht gnola ylesolc gnulc
,pu ekow eloM eht tsal ta nehW
,loof uoy ,siht fo tuo teG"
epoh dna wolloh eht otni
rettum mih draeh eloM eht "!tuo teg
teL' .gnikrow no tnew tcelletni ruoY
yllufreehc flesmih gnillet
".lla ta emoh teg ot m'I fi
!neht woN" ,dias taR eht
dlrow wen lufrednow dna reeuq a otni
,luftsiw dna rednet ,breh-wolliW
ecnetsisrep hcum htiw
,yaw a ni lufitip saw tI
,oot ylisub deparcs eloM eht dna
emit fo tnuoc lla tsol dah yeht—
,egnulp ylrae eht fo kcohs eht neht
enif erew yeht dna
,eloh a morf tnatsni na rof pu dehsalf dah ,seye drah htiw ,ecaf worran
"?uoy yllaer taht sI !yttaR" gniyas
!won lla ti ees I
dehsinotsa eht fo
doow eht hguorht detnuh yltneitap dah eH  "!taR dlo s'ti—
,revo gnol saw remmus llit ton saw ti dna
.ylgnihtoos taR eht dias
.yrenif sti fo deppirts dna ,drah
,tsrif ta sevael gnillaf ylno saw ti thguoht eH
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .2202 ni goD fo ecioV ehT fo edosipe tsrif eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
,evarg yrev dekool taR ehT
yllaer ,taR eht deilper
.yrc gnirewsna elttil a draeh eh yoj sih ot
mih ot lufdaerd os neeb dah taht doow eht was ,tuo gnikool ,dna
.ti was I fi sa nialp sa ,stsixe rood taht' ,uoy syas
,desaec dna yawa deid
,dnuor tnuh dna gid dna hctarcs dna eparcs—eparcs tub
ecilam fo secnalg
?uoy od ,yad-ot kcul hcum gnivah eb ot mees t'nod uoY"
.rehto ro gnihtemos
,ecap sih denekciuq eH
,derolpxe dna dellevohs dna dehctarcs eH
,rehto eht neht dna ,eno tsrif eb ot demees tI
.llah eht otni tuo tnew dna pu tog
,dniw eht dna wons eht fo tuo
,meht ni nrut railimaf a htiw
werg tI .htob neht
nwod elgguns ylno dluoc dna ,rehtruf yna nur ot derit oot saw eh ,wohynA
ruolrap mraw eht fo tuo deppils eh nehw
.yllof siht fo hguone dah d'ew kniht I" ,ylhsittep etiuq
.dnatsrednu uoy ,ereh thgin eht dneps ot od reven lliw tI
,eloh rehtona dessap eH
,ecnetinep ni deirc eh "!taR"
serutcip-enecs ni flesti gnidlofnu
.wap sih ni lotsip a htiw
,drah gninnur ,won gninnur demees doow elohw ehT
,dnik ro tros yna fo gnitaob ta dekcom taht
.yppah yltcefrep er'uoy esoppus I dna
knab revir eht fo tnaegap ehT
.wolloh dednuos taht gnihtemos kcurts
.eloM eht deilper
gnizod yletanretla saw ezalb eht erofeb riahc-mra sih ni taR eht nehw
ffo yaw gnol a etiuq morf dna
.meht dednuorrus taht sepols dna spmuh eht denimaxe dna
"!remmah I elihw ,nac uoy sa drah sa ,drah gnir dna
sgniltsihw eht ot denetsil dna
.ssenesutbo sih ta riapsed ni
spihsdneirf ynam os ,pu derehtag erew sdaerht ynam os nehw
,taR eht deirc "!raed ,O !raed ,O"
teef elttil fo tap-tap-tap eht tub esle gnihton rof ti wenk eh dna
!dooW dliW eht fo rorreT eht—
.spaeh-hsibbur revo emit erom yna etsaw ton dna
,hcuot sti ni elgnit a htiw keehc eht desserac dna ria eht dellif redwop enif A
;erif eht dnuor sevlesmeht dnuof slamina eht nehw syad retniw trohs
.secaf erom on eb dluow ereht
,dooW dliW eht fo elddim eht ni tuoba gniyl reparcs-rood sih tfel sah
,mih ediseb dehcuorc dna emac eloM ehT
,ti woleb dna ,edis eht yb gnuh llup-lleb nori nA
.gel eht ta kool a evah s'teL
niaga krow ot tes eh dnA
rebmuls launna reh ni peed saw erutaN nehw yad retniw taht no sa
'!ti dnif ot tub enod eb ot sniamer esle gnihton s'erehT
liot rehtruf emos retfA
.doow eht fo secalp neddortnu eht otni degnulp dna
detatiseh eH .enog saw dna
,etalp ssarb llams a no
,llams er'uoy fi nwonk eb ot tog
gnihca erew yehT .enod eb ot saw tahw redisnoc dna
,sruoy fo daeh esiw taht ni ,pets yb pets ,tuo ti deugra uoY
mih ecitne dna kcirt dna
,tekcop ruoy ni yrrac uoy stnalp dna
.eloM eht deksa "?yttaR ,pu s'tahW"  "!og—a—
seert fo egnirf tsrif eht dehcaer eh nehw ksud sdrawot gnitteg ydaerla saw tI
,taR eht detpurretni ",t'nevah uoy sa tuB"
.emit a rof efas saw eh
,eloM roop eht dias ",yttaR raeD"  ".gniht eno rof ,dloc ooT
.eloM ,ti enod dna enog evah yllaer t'ndluohs uoY"
".ecalp rieht wonk stam-rooD
.drawrof yrruh mih edam ti wohemos tub
drah lla :dertah dna
,doow eht fo htgnel eht hguorht yllufnam yaw sih edam eH
.noissecorp yletats ni rehto hcae dedeeccus taht
,rood elttil gnikool-dilos a doots knab-
;stops dna stfahs nedlog ynit ni hguorht gnikirts nus eht
niaga gnillewd sthguoht sih dnuof eh taht
,doow siht ot dne on eb ot demees erehT
tsorf dna dloc dna
.reve naht rehto hcae ekil erom dna
".tnereffid yrev os kool gnihtyreve sekam wons siht won dnA
.seert eht hguorht
erab yal yrtnuoc ehT
.worrub yldneirf a nwod
,dooW dliW eht sdrawot no dehsup eh tirips fo ssenlufreehc taerg htiw dna
,tsal ta ti wenk eh
,ti ni eloh a htiw ,eert hceeb dlo na fo toof eht ot
.aes nrehtuos llits emos ni feer kcalb a ekil
,slavretni ta gnikramer
emit retniw eht nI
",emoc t'ndluow eH"  .eloM eht dias
!lla ti no kcab kool ot emac eno nehw
",dnatsrednu etiuq I ,O"  "!kniht t'nac uoy
,revelc os er'uoY
,drow rehtona toN
,gnola ylidaets dehcram dah
.sgniod sti lla dna
,teews-wodaem nehw tuB
,enola saw eh—eh dnA
,ylidaets mih no decnavda ksud ehT
,retniw eht rof thguob tsuj
.wons eht ni gniparcs ysub saw dna mih tfel dah
.efil laer ni erofeb ti ssorca emoc reven ev'I tub ,skoob ni gniht fo tros taht tuoba daer ev'I ,lleW
mih sdrawot drah gninnur emac tibbar a
.hguone erus ,erew yeht erehT
.ylevisave taR eht deilper
.elpmis dna gnorts dna
,elbisiv ylerar hguoht
,lufesoprup dna thgiarts gnola gninnur
,tceffe dna rewop evah hcihw sgniyas dna
,doow eht otni noitatiseh tuohtiw degnulp dna
,mih fo daeha raf dednuos ti
,edistuo dnuorg eht fo ecafrus yddum eht denimaxe ylluferac dna
doow eht fo htgnel elohw eht tuohguorht no dessap dna
,nuf lla saw taht tub ;yawa raf dna
,meht fo sderdnuh erew ereht dna ,raen dna raf ,eloh yreve ,emit eht lla os neeb dah ti fi sa dna ,ylneddus nehT
.dedaeh-thgil gnitteg saw dneirf sih taht saw noinipo sih rof
".drah gniwons s'tI .nwod ,rehtar ro"
,stirips lausu sih ni dna dehserfer hcum
.t'nac ew ,sediseB
!neeb dah ti yalp a tahw dnA
,raey wen eht etarbelec oT dna
".retal noom a fo tib a eb ot thguo ereht dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.1202 ni ediserif eht ta ynapmoc su gnipeek rof uoy knahT
,ylevarb tuo tes yeht ,revewoH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
mih tuoba dereep eH ".hguorht
".ti enod revetahw ,emas eht tsuj struh tI"
,mih dnif uoy sa mih ekat ylno ton tsum uoy tuB
,enola ereh ecaf sih wohs t'ndluow eH"
.esoppus I ,ecnahc ruo ekat dna ,trats a ekam tsum eW"
,regdaB yerg yratilos eht no
gninrom eno tsal ta dna
rorrim eht fo egde eht gnola skcol delgnat tnairuxul gnikahs
,desrepsidnu tey sa
ylneddus nehw ,retaw dna ,ria
,gnitiaw yltneitap yal dna
revir nellows eht dna ,sroodni hcum meht tpek syaw yrim dna
gniugra pots ,ereH"
.swap tnorf sih htob ni gel sih desrun dna wons eht no pu tas eh dna
,dedrawer erew stroffe sih
;pleh yna morf raf dna ,demranu dna
sevil eh esuaceb ,noitseuq eht fo tuo etiuq s'tI
"?tnedor gnitarepsaxe uoy
.laeuqs a htiw ecaf sih no drawrof llef dna
.sevlesruo yb ereh emoc reve yldrah ew ,sreknab-revir eW
,slamina owt eht tnew ti ta draH
.ediserif sih yb dezod ,elbatrofmoc dna mraw
,fo nekops dah taR eht stib ykcommuh eht fo eno gnitagitsevni erew yehT
"!ecnahc tsal ruo s'ti rof
.no edorts dna
.niap sih ni rammarg sih gnittegrof ,eloM eht dias
eert hserf yreve ni dneirf dlo na dezingocer yeht taht
neht dna ;rehtona dna ,rehtona dna
,ti esrevart ot flesmih tes eh
,rethgual sselerac s'taR eht fo dnuos eht yb dereehc yltaerg saw eloM ehT
!deruoloc ylhgih yrev os dna suoremun os snoitartsulli htiW
.worrom eht rof dennalp
,emaharG htenneK yb
,sdnah sih no emit eraps fo laed doog a dah eloM eht ,llits
.trats a htiw ekow eh dna
.ti fo dnuos eht saw etaciled dna thgils os
ecnatniauqca na pu ekirts spahrep dna
,taR dethgiled eht dias "!ees dna emoC"
dehcuorc seert dna
.pmuts a ro hcnarb a yb enod reven saw tahT"
,dooW dliW eht erolpxe dna
?llet dluoc ohw tub ,ytefas neve spahrep—tnemlaecnoc
fo tros a s'erehT
,teiuq s'gnihtyreve fi ees dna edistuo kool a ekat tsuj ll'I
,mih dniheb raf dna ,saw ti llirhs dna tniaf yreV
sgniht fo sedisni eht otni yletamitni os dna raf os nees reven dah eh taht thguoht eh dna
,yawa nworht dna rof enod
morf mih dleihs ot deirt ylniav dah taR eht hcihw gniht taht—
,mih dnuora sselfael yleritne dna
,stnemesuma sti thguorb yad yreve dna
detfird dah hcihw sevael yrd eht otni
.gnilbmert llits dna detsuahxe
.ria nepo eht otni
.yrav ot desufer taht
,ti fo senob erab eht ot nwod tog dah eH
;tros delbuort dna nekorb a fo hguoht
,nihs ym tuc dna llef I taht tnemom yrev eht morf
suoludercni otrehtih dna
,yad-dim toh fo atseis suorougnal eht dellacer yehT
,mih deppirt sgol
,eert hceeb dlo na fo wolloh krad peed eht ni egufer koot eh tsal tA
.tey sa ,t'nod uoy dna tuoba lla dnatsrednu ew hcihw
,ecaf sti ssessop ot demees
;yruf htiw gniggid neht dna erehwyreve legduc sih htiw gniborp
,tahc a rof ni gnippord slamina syawla erew ereht ,esruoc fo ,dna
ev'yeht tub ,meht wonk uoy nehw hguone elpmis lla
,”swolliW eht ni dniW ehT“
uoy ,ereh kool woN"
democlew flesmih dnif ot worrub eht fo tuo emac elom detartsurf a nehw ,oga raey a
no og nac ew spahrep neht dna
.yas dluow taR eht
hcihw gniht daerd taht ,ssenlluf sti lla ni
.yrtne tsrif ta mih mrala ot gnihton saw erehT
,revo ti teg dna ,ot tog ev'uoy fi taht dnuor gij ruoy ecnad dna daeha og retteB
.rehto ro gnihtemos rof emyhr doog a wenk eh fi mih ksa ot eloM eht rof dnuor dekool neht dna
ereh mih ksa uoy t'ndluoC"
,reraen dna reraen
.wollof ot wols ton saw ,duolc tesnus knip a ekil
,tcejbo railimaF
troffe na rof pu flesmih decarb—
,sgniht otni dna sgniht revo llef eh ,sgniht tsniaga pu nar eH .rehtihw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,elihw a rof ytrevop ybbahs rieht koolrevo ot mih ksa ot demees dna
,esirnus erofeb ruoh na
:yojne esaelP   .pihsdneirf dna
.mih pleh dna emoc ot eloM eht dellac neht ;leef dna
,yldipar gniog dna gnimoc
;psarg sih ni legduc ylgu taerg eht dna ,slotsip sih
",thgir lla s'tI" .ffo tup
",yas—ot—naem—uoy—oD"
,ettovag a otni deyarts taht sdrohc yletats ni ti decnuonna dah cisum-gnirts fi sa
,denepo htuom sih
;esuoh eht tuoba sboj citsemod llams rehto did ro
.gnirednop retfa ,taR eht dias
.era uoy tahw s'taht ,rednow laer A !rednow a er'uoy"
,yltneitapmi detiaw eloM eht elihw
.demrala etiuq ,taR eht dias
.dooW dliW eht fo elddim eht ni eloh sih ni
,ti ot roolf yrd a htiw eloh ro evac a ,retlehs fo tros emos dnif dna yrt dna
!ti enod taht reparcs-rood yrev eht dnuof dna ot denrut uoy neht dnA '!reparcs-
,seloh fo tuo deppop secaf elttil dekciw ereht dna ereH
pu gninrut syawla s'eh—
",tuc naelc yrev a s'tI"  "!ym ,O !ym ,O"
rekciht erew seert eht dna
yrd saw taht renroc emos ro evac a rof tuoba detnuh yeht erehw ,lled eht otni nwod delggurts dna
esoht no tuoba klat ot ytnelp saw erehT
,gnisimorp tsom demees taht enil eht koot dna
,lamina suorolav eht fo thgis ta yletaidemmi dehsinav tub
",si ti os ,wonk I ,wonk I ,O"
;ti draeh eh tsrif nehw
,emaharG htenneK yb
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ecap trams a ta dooW dliW eht rof ffo tes dna
,ylrae devirra efirtsesool elpruP
,wodniw eht ta detiaw seidal eht mohw rof thgink eht
,feihcrekdnah sih htiw gel eht pu gniyt ylluferac retfa ,taR eht tuB
,tsaf gnihsinav erew rerafyaw eht ot secanem kcalb rehto dna ,sllaftip ,sloop ,swolloh ,seloH
".pu nrut yam gnihtemos ro ,ffo evael yam wons eht ,sediseB
,kcab llef daeh sih
"!nihs roop ym O" .deirc eh "!gel ym O"
'!devorp si yroeht ym
,flesmih yb efil nwo sih devil ohw
.nageb gnirettap eht nehT
revolc mraw eht tnaw ton did eH
".uoy rof pu ti eit ll'I dna ,feihcrekdnah ym ta teg I llit tiaW .hguone erus ,nihs ruoy tuc ev'uoy"
,wohyna raey fo emit siht ta emoh ta eb t'ndluow eh dna ,yaw gnol a s'tI
.ti ta kcab dehgual
demees esuoh ehT
railimaf gnihtemos ot
,eloM eht dias ",taR ,yllaeR"
,teef rieht no tog yeht erom ecno oS
"?lamina dettiw-llud uoy—uoy ,snaem ti tahw ees uoy t'nod tuB"
,tsim etihw eht nehw
,htmraw rof ,thgim eh tseb sa ,oot ,pu flesmih derevoc taR eht elihw
nrob saw ruoloc dna
,god.ecioveht ta
thgil a ni pu dewohs seert eht fo selob kcalb eht dna
,sgninrom neek llits dellacer
.pu ydobyreve pirt ot erus s'ti erehw tsuj
sesrev dehsinif-flah fo repap siH
,mhtyhr raluger a koot ti werg ti sa nehT
legduc s'taR eht fo tniop eht dna
saw yreaf fo teprac gnimaelg a dna
,eciov elbeef a emac eloh eht fo tuo morf dna
ssenlufreehc elbicnivni htiw gnidneterp dna
,tuo flesmih dehcterts dna
,srettel latipac erauqs ni devargne yltaen
".t'ndluow daoT ,saeniug nedlog fo luftah elohw a rof ton
.sgniht dnuor degdod dna sgniht rednu detrad eh
edis eht nI  .eloM
dellac eh nehT  .teiuq yrev
",ti enod tahw dnim reven ,lleW"
!erew yeht reveohw ,yltnedive ,ydaer dna trela dna pu erew yehT
mih no gnixif lla
"!eparcs dna emoc dna
.ffo sehtolc eht dekcik evah ot demees dna
,yteicoS setah regdaB"
,tsiaw sih dnuor tleb a depparts
,wolloh eht otni tperc taR ehT
.tey tsuj toN .won tsuj ereht og t'now ew kniht I tuB"
.siht htiw tnetnoc eb ot dah eloM ehT
?ereht pots uoy diD
.ssenlufhturt tcefrep htiw ,eloM eht deilper
sknurt-eert kcalb dna ecaps etihw fo ynotonom eht ni
,oow ot shpmyn eht rof yob-drehpehs eht
ro gnihtemos dnuor ni gnisolc ,gnisahc ,gnitnuh
,ti detnorfnoc dna denrut eh nehW
mih erofeb yal hcihw
.esruoc tnereffid a otni mih morf evrews ot ro
dna' ,flesruoy ot uoy syas ',tam-rood a dnif tsuj ylno em
rehto ro yad emos pu nrut ll'regdaB"
tnemom tsekrad rieht sa nwonk dna
.tcaf dilos a s'taht dna taeb daed ylpmis m'I tub ,yrros yllufdaerd m'I"
.tcepsa degnahc a etiuq ni
.gnirats seye sih
,etunim a rof meht revo derop
,gnihtyna rof lufwa oot si dloc ehT
;ylfeirb taR eht deilper ",pu si wonS"
.detaicerppa ylreporp eb ll'uoy erehw og ot thguo uoY
,nopu degagne neeb dah eh tahw gnirebmemeR
,noonretfa eht fo gnihtab dna gnitaob eht
,kcits sih htiw rood eht dekcatta taR eht elihW
"?reparcs-rood a dnuora sgij ecnad yhW ?ti fo tahw ,lleW
.ylpmis taR eht deilper
.ylitraeh gnihgual ,taR eht dias "?daoT dlO"
,deppils laoc a nehT
"?mih no llac dna og ew gnisoppus ,neht ,lleW"
.thgiled dna esirprus reehs morf wons eht no sdrawkcab llef eloM ehT .REGDAB .RM
?dniheb ro tnorf ni ti saW
,nikrej rebma ni suorodo dna rianobed
"—yttaR ,daeh ruoy dah ylno I fI
liah neddus ekil dednuos ti llit
",depleh eb t'nac ti ,llew ,lleW"
,ereht gnuws dna ti dehctulc
,ecap nekcals ot ti gnitcepxe ,detiaw eH
.niaga flesmih erom dna redlob leef ot nageb dna gnirevihs deppots eh dna ,slotsip gnimaelg sih dna kcits sih fo thgis eht yb sa llew sa
!reparcs-rood A .ti llac I
,lla fo tsrow ,dna ,ti ni ecnereffid on dna ,gninnigeb on dna
.erom ecno htrae eht fo tuo gnarps dna
,etihw eht htiw dnah-ni-dnah elprup eht ,yerfmoC