,wap eno htiw eson sih derevoc yelkaO
,sdneirfyob sih htob fo kcart peek ot gniyrt morf detcartsiD
.gnorw saw gnihtemos ebyaM
.pirt siht tuoba erew uoy deticxe woh wonk I"
.yella worran a nwod denrut eh esirprus s'yelkaO oT
,emit a ta eno em ta emoc ot meht ecrof ot hguone worran s'tI" .dias gniK
,tsrif ta detsiser yelkaO
,ffo edorts dna leeh sih no denrut neht dna dekrab yelkaO "!yadhtrib ym nO
.sgniht gninigami eb ot dah eH
"!uoy htiw emoc ll'I ,tiaw ,yelkaO"
.detresed saw hcaeb ehT
,pam eht yawa deppir enO
.yelkaO wollof ot pu gnidnats erofeb flesmih ot derettum eh
,dekrab dna denrut tuons ydoolb eht htiw dnuohyerg ehT
dna yrT .pam eht wollof ot tnaw I
.neddih dah dum eht taht sngised lacituan etacirtni htiw devrac dna doow laer saw tsehc ehT
.hcaeb eht no sgniht fo sriap rof gnikool ,delrihw yelkaO
.rae sih otni delley adnap der dias ",kaO ,ecap eht pu kcip ot tnaw thgim uoY"
.mih retfa deirruh dna riahc egnuol rehto eht morf pu deppoh nedarB
.eulc s'gniK rebmemer ot gniyrt ,gnicar dnim ,elcric a ni nups eH ".ti
,ssaltuc deworrob sih gnuws yldliw ipako ehT
.egatnavda thgieh a em evig lliw ti dna
lworg ot deirt yelkaO "!pu me' kcits ,rrA"  .gniK
,seenk sih neewteb daeh sih tup dna dehcuorc gniK ".sgod
"!spart tsiruot etarip ees ot tnaw I
.liat sih deggaw yelkaO ".yadhtrib
.elzzum sih ot wap a gnidloh
,delworg eh redluohs sih revO
"!sriats eht pu og ,nedarB"
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.moor eht ot kcab daeh dna yella eht piks dluohs eh fi gnirednow ,dewols eH
.erotskoob eht fo tnorf eht ot pu dettort yeht sa dias yelkaO
.gniggid detrats sgod owt eht sa hctaw ot decrof saw yelkaO ,gnilworG
.repap gnipparw lufroloc eht dedderhs dna liat sih deggaw yelkaO "!tseb eht saw tI"
.enaD taerg eht ot gnisol ysub oot saw eh neht tub
.tnemevap eht ot drows freN sih gnippord
.ecap eht pu dekcip yelkaO
".dluow uoy em derussa gniK
.yadot ti fo boj riaf a gniod saw eh tub
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.kcap eht fo tser eht ylbaborP
",yddum lla taoc ym gnitteg er'uoy ,won yeH"
"?reveirter yffulf a dna ,taog ylgu na ,nooccar der A
.senaD taerg eht fo eno htiw gnilaed lluf swap nwo sih dah neht tub
.meht retfa ti pu gnidnuop detrats dna sriats eht dehcaer sdnuohyerg eht htiw mih dlot pmuht gnignir A
.niaga gniggaw detrats dna delrucnu liat s'yelkaO
.seye sih dellor yelkaO ".gniK ,ynnuf yreV"
,lrig yarg eht morf gniws eno tcelfed depleh yelkaO
kool dluow reveirter nedlog a dna ipako na neht tuB
?huh ,yadhtrib sih rof tog nedlog derepmap siht tahw ees s'teL
.ynapmoc eht rof lufetarg saw yelkaO ,llitS
,drows deppord sih deveirter dah dnuohyerg deidoolb ehT
.sriats eht nwod mih gniyrruh ,kcab s'yelkaO ta gnihsup detrats eh nehT
ruf der sadnap der eht htiw gnihsad rehtar dekool kcalb eht llA
.revir eht sdrawot ,yaw taht si tsae ekil skooL"
.ffo gnipmuj morf mih gnipeek
.duol tuo taht yas t'ndid reveirter eht tub
tog tsuj I .niatpaC ,ti toG"
?taeh yggum ,gniretlews siht ni
.htrof dna kcab drows freN sih gnivaw ,sdrawkcab sriats eht nwod gniog saw gniK
.ti dias eh sa gnihgual saw eh tub ,dias eh
.erofeb ti deciton t'ndah yelkaO yhw denialpxe hcihw ,strihs-t gnittif esool ywollib derreferp ipako ehT .riap gniraps eht ta ti devaw dna trihs sih fo tnorf eht fo tuo ebut pu-dellor a dellup nedarB "?ees ,od ew seY"
.hcaeb eht dnuora derettacs seno eht ot lacitnedi ylsuoicipsus dekool taht skcoR
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.emit ta ta kcatta ot eno naht erom rof moor t'nsaw ereht tnaem yawklaw worran eht ,revewoH
erohs eht no retaw eht fo gnippal eht raeh llits dluoc eh weiv sih dekcolb llaw gniniater fo dnik emos hguohtla
.meht retfa delley gniK "!sgod yvrucs uoy
.hgual a tuo dekrab eldoop ehT ".snioc
noinipo s'yelkaO nI
.meht ta sgnaf sih dehsalf eldoop ehT
.tih neeb d'eh taht dezilaer t'ndah yelkaO
.tib a ecap eht pu kcip s'teL"
,yella na ni etarip a thgif drows ot tog I !reve
.pam eht no erusaert etarip eht 'dnif' su pleh uoy evah neht dna ,uoy erutpac ot desoppus erew I dna sgod esohT
.hguone ysae s'taht ,yakO"
.gniK ot denrut yelkaO
.eulc eht neeb dah taht ecnis ,sreteP tniaS no yats ot nedarB detcerid yelkaO tub ,semit lareves dehcnarb teerts ehT
.dnuora gnikool ,detnap yelkaO "?txen tahW"
.SPG s'enohp sih htiw flesmih tneiro ot dnuora decnalg dna detrons yelkaO ".evord
.mih ekil reveirteR nedlog a neeb dah ,ennoB eD ellE
.evord eW ?deggal teJ"
-keew tsal neeb dah sarG idraM
.pam eht tuohtiw niaga ti dnif dluoc I taht wonk t'nod I
.dnas eht otni toof sih deffucs
"!won sruo si erusaert ehT
.tah renroc-irt a gniraew
.sriap ni erew meht fo enon tuB ?seert eht ebyaM
"!dniheb tfel etarip oN .yaw oN"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.seye sih dellor yelkaO
.skcart niart eht sdrawot hcaeb eht otno pu meht neewteb nar epip egral A
.tessab eht dna senaD eht fo eno ta gnitniop ,dias eldoop eht ",uoy dna ,uoY"
# ".pam eht no eulc tsrif eht ot og s'teL"
.s'nedarB ro sih fo eno yreve rof spets ruof ro eerht koot sgel trohs sih htiw gniK
.ylrae gnivael yb ti deniur tsomla uoy tub
.daeh sih gnikahs ,deggurhs yelkaO
.snoitcerid sih rebmemer ot gniyrt seye sih desolc dna desuap yelkaO ",os tnias a retfa deman si teerts ehT
.ylraelc gniK ees dluoc eh
"?ecalp tsrif eht ni ti dih taht seno eht owt uoy t'nereW" .meht fo owt eht neewteb dekool neht dna nwod gniK tes yelkaO
.tiaw dluoc taht tub
.fooh sih htiw stoob s'yelkaO fo eno gnitteg tsomla dna kcab gnippets ,detaelb nedarB
.sessaltuc citsalp eht tih ti sa dekaeuqs drows freN ehT
",054 ro 005 s'taht fi erus ton m'I"
.stleb rieht morf sdrows citsalp gnol werd htob yehT
,sgel s'gniK no pirg mrif a tpek yelkaO tub delggurts gniK
.gnikcatta seno eht erew yeht nehw ,esnopser ddo na saw tahT
.gniwols saw eh neve tub
.spets wef a retfa nedarB fo daeha mih dellup ragus dna hguod deirf fo tnecs eht tub
.enihw yalp yppup dehctip-hgih
,dias nedarB ",ees s'teL"
.meht fo eerht eht dednuorrus won taht kcap sih nioj ot drawrof gnittort
.hcamots sih otno revo dellor dna sdrows citsalp eht rednu daeh sih dekcud eh nehT ".retal
,kcab flah detnac erew srae sih dna eye sih ni kool ytliug a dah ipako eht tub
"!enola yellA etariP erolpxe dna nwod og ot gniog m'I"
.emoc d'yeht yaw eht kcab detaerter sgod eht taht htiW
,gniK gnisol tuoba yrrow ot evah t'ndid eh taht woN
.ediw seye nworb gib sih ,koob sih morf pu decnalg ipako ehT .gnidaer osla
.kcart tsol dah eh
"!dleiy ew ,dleiy ew ,yakO"
.yawklaw eht ta meht dniheb ylsuovren gnicnalg ,deksa nedarB
!erusaert eht ot setarip lavir fo dnab a ecar ot evah ew won dna
,shtap eht ssorca tuc dna erauqs eht fo elddim eht ni niatnuof eht dnuora enog dah yeht yeht emit eht yb ,revewoH
.ecaf rekop elbirret a dah ipako ehT
,relleK nosidaM naI yb
.snioc etalocohc eb t'now wonk ew tsael tA
?meht yb depmud gnitteg eh saW
.eson s'yelkaO dettaws dna pu delruc liat siH
.tuo teef 01 tuoba retaw eht morf pu kcuts snolyp derehtaew dna nekorb fo riap A .detniop yelkaO ".eb
.mih ot kcab ekat ot sartxe tog I"
.teef sih fo sllab eht no decnuob dna niaga sdnah sih pu werht gniK
.deltrats ,dekrab yelkaO "?gniK"
.deticxe os saw eh gnilggiw saw ttub elohw sih tcaf nI
.htron eb dluow tfel ym no neht nuS gnisir eht ecaf I fi oS"
.sgel sih neewteb rethgit delruc liat s'yelkaO .setarip sa desserd sgod deroloc-nat gib owT
.yella eht ni retal su ees emoC
.gninnur tuohtiw spets tnuoc ot tseb sih gniod yelkaO ,erauqs eht hguorht decar yehT
.ti evlos ll'I !mih truh t'noD"
"!reve yadhtrib tseb eht neeb sah sihT"
,tey tih neeb t'ndah ipako eht woh derednow yelkaO
.meht fo htob detcelfed dna thguac taht tsirw sih htiw noitom gnilriwt a did eh tub
stengieb fo gab eht rehto eht
.deppots latem no swap fo dnuos gnignir ehT
,ruf gnol sih revo taoc etarip kciht siht htiw gnikniht neeb eh dah tahW ".retsaF
,pam eht morf duol tuo daer yelkaO ",secap 005 tsae klaw neht ,secaf on htiw senips eht ta tratS"
.tuoba sseleulc m'I trap noom-flah eht tub
,pot eht nepo dellup yehT
.eciov sih otni reehc tcejni ot deirt eH "!won ereh er'uoY
.esolc saw ti dna
"!nwod meht wols ll'I ,oG"
.ecnatsid siht morf yfitnedi ot drah erew sdeerb cificeps esohw ruof rehto eht evoba gnirewot pam eht nelots dah taht senaD taerg evissam owt eht dezingocer eH
"?laer si pam erusaert eht ,tiaW"
.hcrep eht eb ot dah taht tub
.tsehc sih oot tsomla tuo gnillol eugnot sih ,detnap eh "...I"
.efac demeht etarip a saw rood txeN
.su wollof ot evah yeht llA
.drows sih tuo gnillup dna gnippots yb mih rof etabed lanretni sih devlos gniK
...a saw thgir eht no pu gnimoC
.liat sih no nedarB dna gniK htiw teerts eht pu gniggoj detrats dna leeh sih no denrut yltfiws eH ".htron
".dnah yb kcab yaw eht lla gniht siht gniggul ton m'I esuaceb ,bac a llac enoemos woN"
.tuo og ot serised s'yelkaO deromuh adnap der eht yllausU
.noitanitsed rieht ot resolc werd yeht sa deggaw neve liat siH
.nuf dah uoy epoh I"
,yeH" .emoc d'yeht yaw eht kcab ffo koot riap eht neht dna
,gnitoof lauqe tuoba ta mih tup ekil eroM ".egatnavda
.gniK dnuora smra sih gnulf dna denrut eH "!syug uoY"
"!raeg etarip sih ni pu sserd ot ecnahc a teg neve t'ndid nedarB ,kooL
,yawklaw eht no eno yarg eht niojer ot sriats eht pu kcab detaerter eh sa dekrab dnuohyerg eht
,trap siht rof ekil dekool dah pam eht tahw kniht ot deirt yelkaO ".ereht
,sbmil depirts-arbez dna tlep nworb fo noitanibmoc egnarts sih htiw lammam-devooh nacirfA citoxe eht fo dnof nettog dah yelkaO tub
!emit eht tuoba deirrow neeb dah dna eeffoc rof gnippots no detsisni dah nedarB yhw saw siht oS
.sregnif sih neewteb tuo deppird doolB
?kcap elohw ruo tsniagA"
.sriats eht pu tog eh emit eht yb ykahs erew sgel s'yelkaO
.nworb yddum ruf nedlog sih gninrut saw eh taht erac neve t'ndid eH
.yadhtrib ym rof pu siht lla tes uoy eveileb t'nac I"
.teerts eht dehcaer yeht nehw liat sih htiw gnola depoord srae siH
,mih ediseb decap nedarB dna gniK sA
.seye sih dekcirp sraeT
.neht yaw ruoy ti evaH"
.tnemom eht ni yawa deirrac
,dneirfyob adnap-der sih fo taorht eht ot sessaltuc dessorc dloh ot revo tneb eh sa mih dniheb ylsuoiruf deggaw liat s’yelkaO
",pam erusaert a evah t'nod eW"
?esacriats desiar a taht saW
,yellA etariP morf ereh nur dliw eht morf derit llitS
.erow hcae yeht tahw rettam on rehtegot ddo
"!yako ,deticxe saw I
.ecaf s'god eht otni dna edis sih revo deppihw liat dezis-revo s'gniK neht ,gniliar eht otni wolb eht detcelfed freN s'gniK .gniK ta gnuws dna sriats eht nwod detrad dnuohyerg nworb rellat ehT
.enohp sih pu dekcip tub
..nooM ooM elbaffenI eht
.setarip sa desserd lla ,sgod xis fo kcap a saw meht morf ssorcA
.meht dniheb kool ot denrut dna sdrows sih werd eh sa deksa gniK
,dias eldoop eht ",eciohc dooG"
.gnihgual dnas eht otno revo llef dna rethgual htiw dekeirhs gniK
,rethgual gnippiy llitS
.desiar sdrows rieht gnipeek ,ffo dekcab tessab dna enaD ehT
.retsaF .ynA .nuR .t'naC"
dna lamina kcap a saw eH
,revir eht gniwollof thgir devruc daor ehT
.teerts niam eht otno tuo kcab renroc eht dnuora deraeppasid
”esruC s’etariP ehT“   yojne esaelP
.daeh sih evoba swap sih detfil yelkaO
.yella eht fo dne eht ot teg ot tsuj spets 005 em ekat ylbaborp d'tI" .ereht deit senobssorc dna lluks etarip eht gnihsalf
.enaD taerg eht morf tih a tcelfed ot wols oot saw yelkaO
".su htiw pu gnihctac er'yeht dna sdnuohyerg era sgod esoht fo elpuoc A"
,slevon agaS enabsnogarD eht sa llew sa
.tsehc eht no yldnuos sih dekcawht drows reH
.ecap gnihctam a otni llef ylkciuq dna
"?yella eht ot daeh ew erofeb eeffoc dna stengieb teg ot tnaW"
.ylsuoiruf gniggaw liat ,teef sih ot depmuj yelkaO
.sgod eht fo animats eht evah t'ndid eh
.tes dehctam a ro owt ylno deilpmi niwt ,on tub
.ylisae mih derewoprevo sgod evissam owt eht dna ylgnag tub ,llat saw ipako ehT
.epip eht sdrawot srenosirp fo puorg eht dehcram eldoop ehT ".tnellecxE"
.senotselbboc eht no toof detoob a gnipmots ,mih deppots yelkaO "!yaw oN"
.egakcap eht mih detneserp dna denrut eldoop eht esirprus s'yelkaO ot nehT
.mih sa sruot etarip tuoba deticxe sa t'nerew yeht taht esnes elttil a edam tI
.tiftuo eht nwod denot
.eeffoc sih edam ehs sa reh ot klat ot rab eht revo denael saw ohw llugaes a gnivres saw dna tah derenroc-irt a no dah atsirab tac kcalb ehT
"!smossolb gorg gnikcus-eglib ey tsavA" .tsehc s'nedarB ta ti
".god yvrucs uoy ,yadhtrib yppaH"
,spets gnitnuoc ,gniklaw detrats eh
.tuo dettort yeht sa ipako eht ta rae na dekcoc reveirteR nedlog ehT
suorotiart esohT"
.yaw sihT" .kcab daeh d'eh
.semit ynam oot yaw eivom bmud taht dehctaw ev'uoY ?edoc s'etariP"
.adnap der eht ta derats yelkaO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
taht skcor fo elip eht ta nwod gnirats ,srae denettalf htiw doots llits ohw yelkaO ot denrut eldoop ehT ".tnemom
.sgel s'yelkaO dekcilf liat deppit-hsurb s'etalugnu eht taht ipako eht ot esolc os gniyats
!erehT" ...slenitnes niwT
.tsehc eht fo edis eno no eldnah eht debbarg dna eloh eht revo denael gniK ".tuo
,mih nioj ot dediced dah nedarB taht detfil stirips s'yelkaO tsrif tA
,nedarB ro gniK rof gnitiaw tuohtiW ".revir
.eb ot tog s'tI .epip eht yB
.tneserp yadhtrib ruoy laets ot gniog er'yehT"
.drows sih fo dloh peek ylerab dluoc eh dna dehca mra sih swolb wef a retfa
.mih ta gnignul neht ,gniK ta sedalb sih gnihsiruolf
.niatpac etarip a sa desserd saw ohw eldoop etihw yffulf a dna ,dnuoh tessab derae ypoord a ,sdnuohyerg owt ,senaD taerg owt ehT
".em pleh dluohs tahT
.sesnefed citarre sih dedave ylisae sedalb s'tessab dna s'enaD eht tub
.drows sih gnirewol ,dettimda gniK ".on yllautca ...llew ,seY"
".reffoc a ton ,pam erusaert a s'tI"
.edis rehto eht ot dnuora deklaw d'eh ecno niaga detrats dna ecnef eht ta gnitnuoc deppots eH
,rehtegot etad a no og ot thgin tsal em dehctid owt uoy tsriF"
"?egakcap elttil siht tsuj dna tsehc eguh tahT ?ti si sihT"
.ecafrus gnidurtorp yreve morf gnuh dna srettug eht derettil llits sdaeb dna ittefnoc dna-
.rehto eht htiw fooh s'nedarB dna dnah eno htiw wap s'gniK debbarg yelkaO ".em
"?stnih tnaw uoy oD"
,dal riaf ,yrrow t'noD"
-retrauq eht ni thgir ecalp a droffa ot elba neeb dah oirt eht nosaer eht fo trap-
"!siht rof tnemyap meht redisnoC"
mih evag ybsressap eht srae deweks dna seye dellor eht neviG
.pu gnicnalg tuohtiw deddon gniK "?erehw wonk uoY
,keeW krahS ygolohtna eht dehsilbup ohw
",ereh meht taeb ew kniht I ,syuG"
.eldoop eht tpecxe sdrows citsalp dehsidnarb meht fo lla dna
yrruF koob gnitirw yrruf eht dna
.eugnot sih no detlem yllacitcarp hguod mraw eht sa taf dna ragus eht gnirovas ,htuom sih otni etib rehtona deppop yelkaO ".eseht evol d'eH
.meht nioj ot dengied yllanif gniK nehw ti tuoba mih ksa ot devloser eH
.hcrep s'noom-flah eht ot og ot dias tI" .detnap yelkaO "...eulc
.daeh sih evoba sdnah sih desiar dna ssaltuc s'yelkaO deppord nedarB
.terces a peek ot gniyrt saw eh ngis erus a
.ekoj a fo aedi s'gniK saw yltnerappa
.nedarB ot eno dednah ylsseldrow dna sessaltuc citsalp sih werd yelkaO ,sriats eht fo mottob eht dehcaer yeht nehW
,delley gniK "!esirpruS"
.xamilc eht ta m'I ,yelkaO"
,gniK citamsirahc eht gnitad meht fo htob neeb tsuj dah ti tsrif tA
".erauqs dna riaf meht taeb
,liat dnuor eguh a htiw mrof yffulf llams A
.krab a htiw ffo mih tuc yelkaO
.gniws rehtona rof fi sa kcab mra sih dellup gniK no dnuohyerg delzzum ydoolb ehT ".tey
"?uoy did ,skcor em evig yllaer t'ndid uoY"
,erehwyrevE si noitciF
.niaga llef liat siH
.dnuorg eht evoba teef neetfif tuoba yawklaw desiar a otni pu deppets taht ecittal latem worran a saw erutcurts ehT
.krap eht fo elddim eht ni ydaerla erew sgod etarip fo kcap ehT
.ssaltuc sih gnitfil ,delrihw yelkaO
,elcric a otni denethgit sdneirfyob eerht ehT "!kcatta ,sgoD
.gniyas nageb nedarB "--s'ti tuB"
.pu kcab dekrep d'eh skcolb wef a retfA
.tuo siht tfil em pleh ,ereH" ".ekoj a saw tahT
.ecap gnipol siht ta sedirts gnol s'ipako dna god eht htiw neve yats ot gnilggurts ydaerla saw eH
.gnihtemos yb trohs pu thguorb ro delffab saw eh nehw did ti sa dekcilf liat deppit hsurb elttob trohs siH "?yllaer ,gniK"
,enaD taerg eht fo slworg eht gnirongi ,drawrof desserp eH
saw taht ,gnitad saw eh srekoj owt eht gniwonK
.yawklaw eht ot nwod dils gniK dna
.etarip doog a ekam uoy ,yelkaO"
",hcrep s'noom-flah eht ot nuS gnisir eht fo tfel eltsopa eht wolloF"
.meht htiw pu peek ot elba eb dluow gniK ,retsaf yna nar eh fi tuB ".tib
.tespu ro suovren saw eh nehw did eh ekil
.yawa dum erom hsurb ot mra sih fo ruf eht desu eh sa derepsihw yelkaO
.nageb gniK "--llac dluoc I rO"
.no saw eh edis eht morf trid eht fo emos yawa dehsurb yelkaO eerf saw ti taht woN
.sgel sih neewteb gnilruc morf liat sih peek ot gniyrt ,lworg a kcab tib eH
.esruoc degnahc dna deddon nedarB mih fo daehA .dellac eh
.efac eht fo tnorf ni derehtag erew sgod fo puorg A
,yadot sa desserd saw eh eno eht
.tuo delbmut skcor fo hcnub a dna xob eht dednepu eH "...mU"
.ipako eht dniheb morf dekrab senaD taerg eht fo eno
.krap eht dnuora ecnef a ot eud enil thgiarts a klaw t'ndluoc yehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.mih yrrac ot gnireffo yb rehtie sgnileef s'adnap eht truh ot tnaw t'ndid eh teY
esraps eht ni gnicnalg ,dias eh ",tihS"
.enola tuo og ot deirt neve d'eh taht saw eh tespu woh fo ngis a saw ti
,sdnuohyerg htob fo sedalb eht ffo dnef ot gniganam yllautca saw gniK evitcarepyh eht
.spets erom htiw gnignir yawklaw eht raeh dluoc yelkaO dna
dnats t'ndid nedarB
.meht dniheb yella eht fo dne rehto eht ffo dekcolb dah slamina erom owt ees ot redluohs sih revo decnalg dna mih dniheb elffuhs a draeh yelkaO
.ecnayonna sih gnitsacdaorb ,mih dniheb nwod dna pu gnippans saw liat siH
.drows nwo sih deppord eh taht hguone saw wolb eht morf niap ehT
,yella eht fo dne eht ta deraeppa wodahs A
.flesmih pleh t'ndluoc yelkaO dna
.tnuh erusaert laer a ekil ,nuf hcum os si sihT .yaw oN"
.mih dniheb thgir yelkaO htiw klawedis eht nwod yaw sih deppolc ipako ehT ".yaw
.ti tuoba dab taht leef t'ndid eh os ,gnidaer emoh yats ot meht dehctid dah adnap der eht niaga neht tuB
.ni mooz nac ew tub ,llams s'tI
,nedarB ipako eht
".sgnineve eht ni wohs etarip a no tup eW
.gniK tuohtiw ro htiw
.meht retfa dewolleb nedarB
.reve emyhr tseiseehc eht s'tahT"
.delworg gniK ",sgod
.rae no detnac yelkaO
,ni peels ot dednet gniK ecnis sgninrom eht ni rehtegot gninnur neeb dah reveirter dna ipako ehT
.gniK ta gnirats ,deksa nedarB
.klawedis eht no mhtyhr ydaets a tuo deppolc sevooh s'ipako eht ,mih fo daehA
?eulc txen eht s'tahW" .dekrab yelkaO "!oN"
!taht togroF ?stengieB"
.eno ot owt derewoprevo ylraelc erew yehT
.gnildwad hguonE .thgirlA"
.taht ekil gnihtemos ,haey ,hO"
.tib elttil a tuo kcits fo dnik eW
.noitatirri ni gnihctiwt liat depirts-egnaro gnol sih fo pit kcalb eht
".gniht taht htiw luferac eb ,gniK"
,dneirfyob rehto sih erehw ot dekool dna tleb sih ot kcab sdrows citsalp eht htob dehcatta yelkaO
.ten.relleknosidam//:ptth
"?tahW" .dias nedarB ",pam ylno eht elots setarip esoht ...tpecxE" "!og s'teL
.senaD taerg eht ekil ,puteg etarip erow sdnuohyerg ehT
.drows sih dekcik dna niaga swap sih pu werht gniK ".pam
.tneserp ruoy dih dna tuo tnew eW .thgin tsal gniod erew I dna nedarB tahw s'tahT"
.setarip esoht yb nelots steg tneserp ym fi erac t'nod I
.moorb reh deppord erots ecneinevnoc renroc a fo tnorf ni sdaeb dna ittefnoc pu gnipeews xim auhauhihC ynit derruf niht a
.relleknosidam//:ptth ta krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,yb deppolc reveirter nedlog dna ipako eht nehW
.detfil sredluohs s'yelkaO no neeb dah taht thgiew ehT
,riahc rehto eht no denilcer saw
?thgin tsal mih dehctid yeht dah yhw ,llitS
"?...niwT"   .dias nedarB
",tsehc etarip a s'tI"
.niht erew yellA etariP ni sdworc ehT
.swap sih otni ti tsurht eldoop eht nehw egakcap eht gnippord tsomla
.rewop niarb eht eraps t'ndluoc eh
.liat sih dnuora galf senob dessorc-dna-lluks a deit dah dna taoc gnol kcalb a erow adnap der ehT
,regguR .P .B yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
,hgih pu gnihtemos ekil sdnuos hcreP
.dniheb rebmem werc yna evael ot ton si edoc s'etarip eht ,yllanif dnA
.yawa dekool eh dna kcab tnew srae s'nedarB
,koob sih fo segap eht morf pu decnalg ylerab gniK
.gniK htiw swolb dedart eh sa detnap yelkaO
.ereh revo yaw eht no ti tuoba deklat evah thgim I"
!nuf os si sihT"
.ecaf s'yelkaO ot txen thgir wap eno ni dehctulc drows eht dah llits gniK ecnis ,revewoh ,siht eciov t'ndid eH
.tsehc eht fo pot eht ffo trid eht fo tsal eht gnihsurb erew syekcal sih erehw ot kcab dellorts eldoop eht
,weiv etaidemmi sih ni gnihtyna gniees toN ".tnuh
.noitcerid rehtie ni yb dezzihw sraC
.eivom etarip sih dehctaw d'eh sa semit ynam sa tsael ta nees dah gniK taht flehs rieht no eivom eno tsael ta fo gniwonk ,baj eht derongi yelkaO
",sriats eht fo mottob eht ta nwod em tuP"
?siht ekil gnitca eb yeht dluow esle yhW
”esruC s’etariP ehT“ saw sihT
!nelots steg ti fi erac t'nod I"
",ytoob eht fo draug dnats slenitnes niwT"
.ittefnoc ekil ria eht otni dnas fo slufdnah werht dna
adnap der eht gniyrrac dna stsiruot gnigdod elihw klawedis railimafnu eht no nur ot gniyrt htiw tub
.tah sih detsujda dna deggurhs adnap der ehT ".reve
.thgil eht gnikcolb
?su pots ot gniog s'esohw dnA ?haeY"
.neercs eht morf daer nedarB
...koob ym ni pu thguac tog tsuj I
,adnap der a rof evitca yrev saw gniK elihW
.meht dniheb dekrab god a "!syob ,me' teG"
.delworg yelkaO "!reveN"
.taorht sih ta pit eht tniop ot drows reh detfil dna dennirg enaD ehT
.pets a kcab mih dekconk lairetam ffits eht taht gniws eht dniheb ecrof hguone saw ereht tub
.gniK gnimriuqs eht htiw yawklaw eht ssorca dereggats eh ,drah gnitnaP
.uoy fo eno dna meht fo xis era ereht ,dnoceS"
...eulc eht fo trap tsal eht ,yakO"
.adnap ,nuf neeb s'ti lleW"
",hguone gnol neeb s'ti sseug I"
"?huH"  ?sterces eroM
detniop dna drows a werd meht fo tnorf ni etteuohlis ehT .yadhtrib a tahW
,enog ydaerla erew sgod owt eht tub
.ereh t'nsi gniK dab ooT"
.snolyp eht morf hcaeb eht pu tsuj htrae nworb rekrad fo erauqs a was eh ,resolc tog yeht sA
",neht tsrif ereht daeh nac eW"
,etarip etirovaf sih tcaf nI
”esruC s’etariP ehT“
.gnikcartkcab ,dias yelkaO
.sdnah ytpme won sih ta nwod gnikool ,detaelb nedarB ",oN"  .sdrows sih gnihtaehs ,defoow yelkaO
.skcor uoy evig t'ndid ew oN"
,nedarB tsap depael dna sessaltuc citsalp owt sih werd yelkaO
.gniK htiw gnirraps detrats d'eh nehw meht tuoba nettogrof dah yelkaO
,pirt edis s'nedarB retfA .dias yelkaO
"!enod erew ew nehw thgin tsal enohp ym htiw ti fo erutcip a koot I ,tiaw ,hO"
;swap sih detfil dna drows freN sih deppord gniK
.adnap der eht gniyrrac elihw ipako eht htiw pu peek t'ndluoc eh
...retfa deneppah taht tuB"
.klawedis eht dehcaer yeht nehw dias nedarB ",yrros m'I"
.acirfA ni kcab retsis ym ot dnes oT"
.retal uoy htiw setarip yalp ll'I
.esneffo ekat t'ndid tub ,ecnayonna ni deffuh yelkaO
.enif saw sdneirfyob sih htiw pihsnoitaler siH
.gniK ta hteet sih derab eH
.yella eht fo llaw kcirb eht otni senotselbboc eht ssorca decnuob edalb freN ehT
.gnola mih gniggut
.gniK no dednuor neht
.edistuo eht no sniats esaerg dah ydaerla taht gab repap nworb a pu dleh ipako ehT ".mih
.yadhtrib sih no ti od ot ecin oot erew yeht tub ,mih htiw pu kaerb ot detnaw yehT
.daor regral ylthgils a otno detixe yella eht erehw edis rehto eht ta wolg eht morf emac thgil ylno ehT
.thgirla s'tahT"
.dekrab ehs ",dleiY"
"!nalp eht t'nsi sihT"
,regguR .P .B yb uoy rof daer
"?yllaer ,esruc s'etariP"
.rewsna na rof gnitiaw tuohtiw dessap tsuj d'yeht efac eht sdrawot kcab yelkaO dewot nedarB
.rehtegot kcab gnag sih derehtag dah eldoop ehT
,emit emas eht ta detcejbo gniK dna nedarB "!yeH"
"!tneserp yadhtrib s'yelkaO laets ot gniog er'yeht yrruh t'nod ew fI
"?pleh deen uoy oD"
?setarip yb deggum dna htiw pu nekorB
.daor eht ssorca dehsad dna ecaps worran eht fo dne eht ot tog yehT ".yella
"?ti tog ,sdrow naht erom evah ll'ew ,niaga kcap ym fo yna truh uoy fi tuB
.no meht devaw gniK tub dewols yelkaO dna nedarB
.tuons sih morf gnilkcirt llits doolb elttil a htiw hguot yrev gnikool smra sih dessorc dna dehpmurrah gniK .ytilibissop a yllautca
"!ti teg ,si ti erehT"
.kcab sih dniheb swap sih decal dna nwod dehcuorc eH ".dniheb
.detsuahxe er'uoY" .delworg gniK ",yelkaO ,nwod em tuP"
.ereht teg ew nehw suoivbo emoceb lliw ti yllufepoH
"!srebbuldnal ey ,rekcoL 'senoJ yvaD ot uoy dnes ll'ew ro pam erusaert ey revo dnah ,woN" .drows sih dehsiruolf gniK
".snoitcerid su evig nac ehs fi ees dna reh llac ll'I"
.mih derongi dna sriats eht pu gnignalc ydaerla erew sgod eht tub
.gniK dna yelkaO wohs ot neercs enohp sih tuo dleh nedarB
.edisni espmilg a teg ot yrt ot kcen sih gninarc
,pot eht morf meht dehctaw sdnuohyerg fo riap ehT
,owt s'yelkaO ot drows eno dah ylno gniK
a fo erom sa tuo emac sdrow sih tub
,esirprus ni deknilb yelkaO "?tahW"
.seye sih morf rethgual fo sraet gnipiw ,doots gniK
evah dluohs eh ebyam
.tey eulc tsal eht tuo derugif t'ndah I"
,mih gnittih morf drows s'god gib eht peek ot deganam eh elihW
.deksa nedarB "?won tahw ruO"
.gnola yalp d'eh ,llitS
.meht retfa tuo derettulf repap A
.yldliw gniws srae yppolf sih gnikam ,daeh sih koohs yelkaO
,wap sih ni dnah s'nedarB koot yelkaO .elzzum sih no elims a decrof eh litnu tnemom a rof dah sih tsniaga denettalf srae s'yelkaO .gniyl rO
.tfel tsuj d'yeht yella eht fo htuom eht ot kcab noitnetta sih werd meht dniheb krab A
,detsetorp nedarB "...retfa
,citsalp saw ti ,sih ekiL
.liat sih no yelkaO dna gniK htiw hcaeb eht nwod dettort yelkaO
.nedarB tsniaga pu demaet dnuoh tessab eht dna enaD taerg rehto ehT
".derebmuntuo uoy evah eW
.yella eht fo dne rehto eht tuo sooragnak fo puorg a del etarip a sa desserd eldoop nworb A
,fooh tilps eno htiw klawedis eht deffucs eH "...koob
.neercs eht ta detniuqs dna enohp eht koot yelkaO ".ni
.fooh sih gnippat yltneitapmi mottob eht ta doots dna edis rehto eht no spets eht fo mottob eht ot ti edam ydaerla dah nedarB
.sdrows nwo rieht dehsidnarb nedarB dna gniK ,mih fo edis rehtie nO
,ti daer dna ria eht fo tuo ti dehctans yelkaO
.teiuq dna ytpme saw teerts eht esiwrehtO
,pirg sih denesool yelkaO ".detsuahxe
.ti yb tespu taht t'nsaw eh gnileef eht tog yelkaO dna deggurhs nedarB
.drows sih deppord dna esirprus ni depley dnuohyerg ehT
ipako ehT  .selggig otni devlossid eH ".degats
.yelkaO tsap gnippiks ,dias gniK ",ylsuoivbo s'nedarB" "?s'nedarB ro 'secap' ruoy ,tiaW"
.polf srae etihw derruf-ylruc sih gnikam ,daeh sih koohs god ehT
.gniK ta detrad sdnuohyerg owt ehT
.noitamrofni yna eldoop yllub eht evig ot gnisufer ,smra sih dessorc oot nedarB
.tsehc erusaert nedoow demod a dehtraenu ylkciuq yeht dna ,swap rieht morf deyarps triD
"!truh taht ,luferac eb ,yeH"
,esirprus yadhtrib ruoY
.niapS dna ecnarF fo stac eht yb ylniam denwo spihs eht dnuoh dna kcatta ot skcap etarip demrof dah taht sgod fo sdeerb suoirav neeb dah setarip fo tol A
.gnorw saw gnihtemos erus saw eh woN ".taht
"!reffoc ruo dna su tcetorp ll'I
.ydaer er'uoy nehw pu hctac ,gniK"
.thgin tsal tops a ot su dael ot mussopo lacol a derih ew tpecxe ,haeY"
.enohp sih tuo gnikat
;rehtegot egnarts elttil a
.sgel sih neewteb delruc liat sih
.klawedis eht no ciffart toof
.klawedis eht no doots yeht sa dettimda eh
,yldab os edisni og ot detnaw yelkaO
,yella eht fo dne eht ot resolc saw eh taht woN
,srekaerb evaw fo enil a saw retaw eht nI
.noisiv thgin tuohtiw serutaerc lanruid htob er'eW .krad saw tI
.repap gnipparw yadhtrib ni depparw mra s'yelkaO sa gnol sa tuoba egakcap elgnatcer a tuo dellup eldoop ehT
.sgod esoht yb deniur tog ti yrros ,llew ,haeY"
,yadhtrib sih no nuf evah ot gniog saw eH
.toob ot wolfria sih fo trap ffo gnittuc saw kcen sih dnuora pirg s'gniK dna adnap eht pu gnidloh fo troffe eht morf denrub smra siH
.gniK ,uoy rof tog I stengieb eht koot neve yeht dnA"
;dniheb nellaf dah yelkaO
.sriats eht fo pot eht morf meht gnieye sdnuohyerg eht ees ot kcab decnalg eH
"?yawyna ,erusaert laer a ot del pam eht taht wonk sgod eht d'woH"
.kcen s'yelkaO dnuora smra sih parw dna pu pets ot dlohdnah eht desu tub detrons gniK ".semit
.oirt ylop a fo erom neeb dah ti yletal os
.eulc eht tuo erugif ot evah neve t'now sgod esohT"
"?deirub erusaert siht s'erehw ,woN"
.weiv morf revir eht dekcolb taht llaw gniniater eht revo yawklaw nairtsedep desiar a ot del ti ekil dekool tI
.nevo eht morf hserf dna mraw meht gnivah ton yb ydaerla tuo gnissim saw gniK
.nooM ooM elbaffenI eht
.em htiw tuo gnah naht daer rehtar d'uoy won dna
"?esirprus yadhtrib eht fo trap t'nsaw tfeht pam eht taht ti ekat I"
,daeh sih evoba devaw liat depirts gnol siH
.no owt rehto eht derehsu yelkaO ".tib
"?hctac ot detnaw uoy gnihtemos ro wohs a ereht sI"
.gniK ta dekool neht
,mih pmud ot gnitnaw fo meht detcepsus d'eh taht ytliug tlef eh won tuB
.sgnaf derab htiw ecaf yrgna tseb sih gnikam ,daeh sih revo drows sih devaw gniK ".gniK
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  relleK nosidaM naI yb
.ereh regnorts hcum saw retrauq eht ni deregnil dah taht eniru fo llems tneserp-reve ehT
"?stengieb ym tuoba tahw ,yeH"
".deggal tej elihw seulc elbavlos tey citpyrc htiw pu gnimoc yrt uoY"
.ezeerb eht ni tel ot nepo ediw gnuws erew edisni gnidael srood elbuod ehT
.trid eht fo tuo tsehc gib eht deltserw yeht rehtegot dna edis rehto eht koot nedarB elihw gniK denioj yelkaO
"!tol uoy ot yelsgniK niatpaC s'tahT"
.yltpurba deppots neht tub
.wap sih gnuts ti detcelfed eh emit hcae
.rehto hcae htiw kcab-ot-kcab
.woleb skcor eht ot nwod llef dna ecittal eht fo stals eht neewteb deppord drows citsalp niht ehT
,gnitadimitni kool ot ,serutaef yffulf dnuor sih htiw ,adnap der ynit eht rof drah saw tI
,edis rehto sih nO
.ezirp ruo pu gid oG"
.degats saw kcatta etarip ehT"
.sredluob dna sdeer lla saw ti erohs eht ot resolc tub ,skcart niart eht ot esolc efil ot gnulc seert wef a dna ssarg esrapS
dekool stiftuo rieht fi nevE
saw noom – flah eht tahw erus t'nsaw llits eH
.eerht uoy ,pu ti eviG"
.gniK ta kcab dekrab owt eht fo delcsum erom eht
.tros emos fo tnemunom llams a dnoyeb tsuj teerts eht fo edis rehto eht no revir eht ees dluoc eh ereh morF
.stoob citnehtua ot nwod tah derenroc-irt a morf ,ailager etarip lluf ni yelkaO dna trihs-t dezis-revo na dna strohs ni desserd nedarB
tneserp yadhtrib tseb eht si sihT"
.dennalp d'ew esirprus eht tuoba reh gnitxet saw I
.sgnikram kcalb dna
.mih degguh dna pu kcab gniK detfil yelkaO "?deniuR" ".tneserp
.em nettog evah dluoc uoy koob ro yot revetahw naht retteb yaw a si sihT
.nettogrof stunod
",ffo tsrif ,freN si drows ruoY"
.tneserp yadhtrib sih pu gnittes tuo neeb d'yeht nehw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,derekcins nedarB