,floWcaM boR si sihT
siht ekil taorht ym htiw kaeps t’nac I ,on—
.llacer t’ndluoc I
.noom lluf yreve radnelac ym tuo kcolb ot evah won d’I fi ro
,regguR .P .B yb uoy rof daer ,nosrednA esahC yb
,ni gnidih neeb d’ti eloh eht fo tuo lwarc ssensuoicsnoc ym did ffo derebmul ti retfa ylno saw tI
,oN ?raeb a taht saW
,sracs yna tfel t’ndah retnuocne eht tub—
.nooM ooM elbaffeni eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.shtgnerts ruo otni sesruc ruo gninrut rof dna
,pu delkcub dna taes ym otni delffuhs I
;gnihton rof t’nsaw tI
.enim eb ot dah ti
.gnol os rof ekawa em peek ylno dluow eeffoc renid
.tnarg reve dluoc T naht erom yaw dna kciht dna lluf ,riah tlef I
.rewop dna ssam siht lla niatsus ot seirolac hguorht wehc dluow ydob ym ,llits deniamer I fi neve
,ediserif eht ta ereh
:kcen ym ni gniht emos fo hteet eht tub
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.nrecnoc tseggib ym emaceb ylneddus yrautibo ym ecarg dluow ecaf gnorw eht
,ytivarg fo llup yrgnuh eht ron
.em morf emoc dah ti dna
.ruf dna sgnaf htiw egar
,melborp s’em erutuf eb dluow taht tuB
.tsetorp ni gnilbmurg selcsum eros ,hcneb eht ffo dils I dna devirra edir yM
,seirots edirP htiw pu emoc ot deksa fi
.saw ti thguoht I eramthgin eht t’nsaw siht spahreP
.erom emos nar I neht dna ,denrub selcsum ym litnu nar I
;deb otni despalloc I erofeb rewohs ot dedeen I
.em deluam taht flowerew gnikcuf a saw tahT .ruf ehT
.gnihtyna fi ,tuo em dewollem T
,sretfihsepahs gnieb rof
dda dluoc sracs ehT
tey tluda na rof hguone lanoisseforp
nwod gniflow retfA
erofeb naht rewol saw eciov yM ”.em s’taht ,puY“
,dnuorg eht ot em thguorb dah taht hcamots ytpme ym ni sreeb thgil wef eht t’nsaw tI
,tnemevom yreve htiw gnillor thgiew eguh ym fo gnileef eht gnirovas
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
”airohpsyD redneG rof tnemtaerT levoN a sa yporhtnacyL fo noitacilppA ehT“ saw sihT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?ereht pu rehtaew eht s’woh ,yeH“
a saw erehT .laer saw siht
.sehtolc ym erew roN
:rohpatem tpa na si
,doof fo htrow 05$ )rah rah(
.syawyna gnivird nageb eh tub ,decnivnoc mees t’ndid eH ”.erus ,haeY“
.yaw gnivig swap ym htaeneb senots dna sgiwt dna trid eht
.eman ym detats revird eht dna rood eht denepo I
.gnitnioppasid saw hcihw
.yaP elppA koot yeht tsael tA
?erutcip eht detadpu I dah tub ,ppa eht no eman ym degnahc I wenk I ”.eno dlo na ,hu ,s’tI“
.ereht t’nsaw ti tub ,enohp ym rof delbmuf sdnah yM
,srehto truh ot rewop siht esu ot erised on saw erehT
.gnissap ot yek eht saw taht iouq sias en ej taht
.niap fo dlrow a otni deye-
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”airohpsyD redneG rof tnemtaerT levoN a sa
.roolf tserof eht ot senip eht fo shguob eht gnitartenep thgil s’noom lluf eht htiw
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
seirots s’rohtua eht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,retirw noitcif evitaluceps a
ygolohtna ”,kcoR seduD“ gnimochtrof eht ni dnuof eb nac yrots sihT
.seohs ym fo sniamer eht htiw gnola ,sehtolc dedderhs ym fo sroloc eht was I
dioR’ ?laed elohw s’yporhtnacyl taht t’nsaw dna
”airohpsyD redneG rof
”.erutcip ruoy ekil kool t’nod…uoY“ .deksa I
tnemtaerT levoN a sa yporhtnacyL fo noitacilppA ehT“yojne esaelP
yporhtnacyL fo noitacilppA ehT“
,ecnatpecca gnigdurg fi gniworg htiw detaert won dna dezinomed ecno gnieb rof
.stnioj detfihs eht ,sdap kcalb kciht ehT
.nooM ooM elbaffeni eht
.egamad eht ssessa ot taorht ym ot tnew dnah A
,regguR .P .B yb daeR
.namuh ylsaem a sa gninrom txen eht s’ynneD eht otni delbmuts I nehw dekan eb t’ndluoc I dna
,edirP yppaH  .stsacdop ruoy
,relgnarw teehsdaerps
;rehtie ,erofeb em ot deneppah t’ndah tahT
.thgir erom ,retteb
.evom ot tey dah revird eht tub
htaerb ym sa taorht ym gnilttar ,tsehc ym morf detpure lwoh A .noillim a semit tub
.drib tenretni dna
.taht ekil pmuj t’nod yeht
,rehtohcae ni htgnerts gnidnif rof
.riah dna niks ym ot gnulc taht trid dna taews eht rednu god fo ffihw taht thguac llits I ,namuh rekaew
.stsev ”suovren m’I !tuo hctaW“
.emoh teg yllanif ot tfyL a dellac I
,tohs T tsrif ym morf hgih eht ekil saw tI
.noitces s’nerdlihc eht ot detageler yllamron ezis eht ni llits
nosrednA esahC yb
ylbaborp ,gnilwoh taht lla morf taorht eros—
.ti tuoba gnihtemos od dluoc taht txet dluoc I elpoep—
,dnif ot reverof nekat dah taht seno ehT
,sretirw yrruf fo puorg nevig yna spahrep oS
.ti hguorht dedrac slian prahs won dna ,riah erom nevE
,lla retfa ,flowerew A
llac dluoc I elpoep erew erehT
.lla ta gniht a t’nsaw taht ebyam rO
.dellems I sa dab sa dekool ylbaborp ti
.teef ym ot derebmalc I sa em morf yawa tohs dnuorg ehT
,nosrednA esahC yb
.esahc ,etisbew sih no
”?gnorw gnihtemoS“
.yrots flowerew a evah ot
.retal ro renoos sevlowerew no egrevnoc ylbativeni lliw
.yrarbil a fo daetsni esuoH elffaW eht dniheb tuo gnuh syawla sevlowerew neetruof fo kcap lacitehtopyh eht yhw ylbaborp saw tahT
,lworg peed a ,wol saw eciov ehT ”.kcuF“
gnileef gnihtyreve fo esnes ehT
,retrohs a sa nevE
,llems fo esnes ym htiw yek eht dnif ot drah t’nsaw tI
,]b[sserP acitamsirP morf noos elbaliava
,sruof lla no ,nar I neht dnA .gnos otni denrub
,noitidart htnoM edirP tnetrevdani na emoceb s’tI   .zyx.esahc
,relevart wollef ruoy
,deipucconu ,nibac a dnuof I
;tihs ot deffucs kcab eht dna dekcarc saw neercs enohp ehT
,taht llet dluoc I
wolley esoht fo eno gniraew flowerew a was reven uoY
.loots-pets a no gnidnats ekil saw tI ?swaP
,sehtolc yna tuohtiw emoh teg dluow I woh htiw gnola
.daeh ym delooc tI
.flowerew gnikcuf a won saw I
.eroc ym ni delriws ygrene gninrub a
,thgirb ylgnisirprus saw thgin ehT
.retsiger ot thgis eht rof stnemom lareves koot ti dna dnah ym ta dekool yllanif I
.tneserp eht ot kcab dnim ym deppans noitasnes gniredliweb dna knarf ehT
;niks ym ta dellup selcillof gnivom ehT
.elbativeni spahrep saw siht ,thgisdnih nI
,tihs gnikcuf yloH
.doog yna em od dluow rewsna eht gniwonk fi sA ?noil niatnuoM
.sehtolc emos ”deworrob“ I ecno enohp ym rof kcab tnew I dna
.doolb dna trid dna lamina tew fo gnikeer ,laitseb ,tneloiv
yraelb dna gniknilb
,eman gnorw eht taht ytilibissop laer yrev ehT
,selcsum ym otni gnipees rewop