yreppep ylthgils dna wolley tnaillirb—tsaper eht fo etib rehtona deganam aetnaP ”.rehtoM ,gninrom yreve taht yas uoY“
.llird a taeper ehs gnidnamed
,aqrahsla fyas reh fo eldnah eht pirg ot nwod
.wap s’nirihS gnikat ,detneler aetnaP
noitcartta gniremmis eht no pu dekcip dah rehtom reh gnilkni na dah drapoel gnuoy ehT
,drawnwod ylbitpecrepmi tsomla gnipolS   ”.nosaer doog rof
.norffas dercas fo sdnorf etaciled yb dednuorrus stops drapoel fo nrettap a erob hcaE
’egnellahc‘ siht tahw dlot neeb t’nevah llits I“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.draytruoc roiretni eht fo sllaw eht dnoyeb tuo gnikeep
.eripmE eht fo sdog eht rof
sredluohs sih dnuora kaolc dedooh eht
,rafuoliN morf teksab eht koot nirihS
reyarp fo riap a devomer rafuoliN ,erutseg reh tA .drawnwod gnitniop regnif xedni reh htiw tuo wap reh gnidnetxe ,taes reh morf esor avraF ”.lla su no enihs adzaM aruhA fo thgil eht yaM
sdnas nedlog eht otni derutnev
delkcirp niks s’aetnaP  ”.meht
partaS eht ,dekram era uoy ecnO“
”.yaw eht gnidael er’uoy fi esoppus I“  ”?yas uoy od tahW“
gnuoy oot kool uoY“
.elpmet eht fo traeh dnuorgrednu eht dehcaorppa noos yeht
puc retaw yalc reh ffo deppot drapoel naisreP redle ehT
.egap ytiniffaruF sih ta
,regnarts on era uoY“
.yllacitpeks deksa aetnaP ”?reverof evil ot
?senots kraps ruoy evah llits uoy oD“
,iluzal sipal dehsurc htiw deyd erew skeehc siH
degnellahc si drapoel gnuoy a taht yad yreve ton si tI
kraM rieht denrae htrib elbon fo
”.txet evitcurtsni…na fo erom dna
,swodahs eht morf tuo deppets xnyl A
ruf demmirt-ylprahs yb detautnecca—sredluohs daorB
”.egnahcxe ni gnihtemos elttil a si rof ksa I llA
,sffur keehc s’drapoel eht delsuot htaerb toH
fayS a fo noitanotni prahs eht htiw swap reh deppalc nirihS ”?tog
,aqrahsla fyas reh werd ehS
.hsurb eht hguorht dennacs ehs sa seye reh deworran aetnaP
evah ew nehw rof tiaw rehtar d’I“
ylmrif swalc ekil-nopmarc reh hcnup ot reh deriuqer sedirts wef tsal ehT
”!rehtoM ,uoy evoL !eyb ,yakO“
nopu yvaeh eil noos lliw ezag gnicreip riehT
aH“  ”.regnarts ,tsrif knird uoY“
.ratrom dna enots tsuj s’tI“  ”.dehctaw…leef I“
.htraeh eht ot revo gniddap erofeb ffo deird ehs sa denrub skeehc s’aetnaP ,lluks reh tsniaga talf gnidlof sraE
”kraM s’partaS ehT“   yojne esaelP
.taht em evig ,ereH“
gnidnelb ykrej decips ylhcir fo stnanmer
.ruf ydnas reh htaeneb elbisiv selcsum gniglub reh fo eniltuo eht ,kcen reh dekcarc lacarac ehT .tnecsed eht raelc ot eert delrang a hguorht dehsals nirihS ,rihsmahs reh fo gniws a dniheb ydob reh fo ecrof lluf eht gniworhT
.tlas deifirup sa etihw dehsalf yks eht sa
.eadagrasaP eht fo sllah renni eht ni—
,raelc I mA .yaw eht no uoy fo rehtie morf roivahebsim on tnaw I
.deksa nirihS ”?rewop tahW“
.meht fo tseb eht htiw ereht pu ydaerla er’uoy kniht I
dna tsrif tekram eht ta pots dluoc ew gnikniht saw I“
sirgrebma fo rixile gnillems-teews a htiw teef s’rethguad reh hsaw ot revo tneb avraF  ”.eripmE
kagnas delpmid fo hcnul a gnikcap flesreh deisub—
elbaliava gnihtyna naht tnetop erom raF“
.rewop laropmet fo tiusrup eht ni sevil rieht fo āhnA evirped ton dluohs enO“
.msitengam egnarts htiw deubmi saw eciov s’demhsaH ”?ereh deronoh ecno erew taht
,denepo snevaeh eht sA
.gnirrrb cillatem a htiw gnirettalc draknat
”?sgnileef ym
.erohs yddum eht ot ylwols flesreh deggard aetnaP
.kcab dooh sih werht xnyl ehT
.ria ytpme hcuot ot ylno
,em pleh os ,sedapacse suoveihcsim ruoy htiw
,reh dniheb hceeb fo knuh eht gnimmalS
nialpdoolf nerrab eht
.demusnoc yllausu ehs reeb llams ro eniw deganu eht naht tnetop erom raf saw tI
.daeha yltnedifnoc gnisserp ,dias nirihS ”,fo
,nirg gnikcom a htiw dias demhsaH ”,lataf ton s’ti
.nasitra trepxe na fo wap eht yb delesihc hcae
.derettum aetnaP
.llat worg taehw ruo yam dna sdleif ruo otni detpurretninu wolf srevir eht yaM
?ydnah dor gnihsif taht evah ot neppah…uoy oD“
”?pu pils ot dewolla ton m’I ,oS“  ”.worb ruoy
”.gninthgil yb kcurts teg rethguad reh tel I fi em llik dluow rehtom ruoY“ .dias nirihS
t’nerA“  .plug elgnis a ni redniamer eht denwod nirihS sa gnihctaw ,deilper aetnaP ”,setunim wef a ni evom ot doog eb dluohs I .haeY“  ”?retteB“
.emufrep gnitacixotni na mrof ot
.won su raeh ,elpmeT rennI eht fo droL
”?eno evarb eht uoy
.noitapicitna htiw spil reh gnikcil ,dias ehs ”,hcnul cincip a teg
.raewrednu gnol htgnel-elkna fo riap a ni reh gnivael
.shtolc-hctac ni llits srelddot
.thgir rieht ot ffo gniraelc nworgrevo na morf tuo dekeep
,remmiws tpeda na elihW
”.anera gniniart eht ta ton s’ehs nehw stnaw ehs tahw od ot dewolla si nirihS“
”?tcerroc I mA .tseuqnoc eht erofeb sdnal eseht nees evah ot
erahs…uoy oD“ .dessefnoc ehs
,enola gnidnats ,drapoel a fo erugif a ot nward ylevitcnitsni saw ehS
.hteet reh tsniaga nedael denrut eugnot reh sa nottoc fo lluf deffuts ylneddus saw elzzum s’aetnaP ”.cigam doolb fo taht…ecrof tnetop erom dna redlo na fo esruoc fo kaeps I“
.NGISLLAC htiw
erafhguoroht detresed a nwod nirihS dewollof aetnaP ”.ti yb ssap ew emit yreve speerc eht em sevig elpmet denodnaba ehT ?ot evah ew oD“
”.doog cilbup eht rehtruf ot
.stceffe gnitades s’breh eht thguof eh sa stekcos rieht fo tuo gniglub seye sih
elihw buc gnuoy a ekil reh moorg ot nageb rehtom reh sa denaorg aetnaP
erofeb ecno roloc eht nees ylno dah ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,asonyeR saw drapoel eht hguoht sa drawpu aetnaP deggut nirihS .tsirw reh dnuora depmalc wap mraw a ,liaf ot nageb htgnerts reh sa tsuJ
eid uoy erehw trap tahT“
.elballys hcae htiw derrup yllacitcarp xnyl ehT
”.gnorts etiuq s’tI .haeY“  ”?yako uoY“
.enots looc eht tsniaga gnitser keehc
sdog eht tegrof toirtapmoc lufhtiaf a dluoW
dehgis aetnaP ”.uoy knahT“
.erus rof s’taht ,nadamaH ni raazab eht ta
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
detfihs liah eht
.swap sih ni droc gnidnib a htiw
.dnats ew hcihw nopu lios eht no deplehw saw I tuB“
,sgniward etacirtni htiw derevoc
”?elkcirt digrut siht ot dleiy iotanahtA gnitcepser-fles a dluoW !retsaF“
ygolohtna wen eht morf eceip elpmas a gnireffo
.erats gnicreip a htiw reh dednamirper rehtom reh erofeb gur eht otno pets ralugnis a koot aetnaP
.tuo depmats yleritne tsomla dah partaS eht taht eno
”.daeha yad eht rof htgnerts ruoy deen ll’uoY
”,gnissorc revir eht tuoba noitseggus ssalc-dlrow …mM“
,edis rieht no nar taht sehctid eganiard tnangats eht morf dekaorc sgorfllub evisavnI
.ylesolc uoy devresbo dna srotut ruoy ot
”.selur tnereffid yb evil yehT
.rood tnorf eht raen nisab gnihsaw eht ta rehtom reh denioj dna denrut drapoel eganeet eht ,hteet reh hguorht ecnayonna fo tnurg a gnisaeleR
,gur reyarp eht no deggel-ssorc gnihcreP
.pets rehtona deganam ylerab drapoel eht
niaga ecaep s’partaS eht nekorb ev’uoy taht drauG ytiC eht morf raeh I fI .emit siht
.spordniar gnillaf fo ecnagele eht htiw
.sthgin ytriht dna
rihsmahs reh fo egde dekciw eht desu yllanoisacco ehS
”…gnorts oot elttil a ebyaM“  ”.erus
ruf reh deird ehs ,nisab gnihsaw eht fo tuo gnippetS .deilper avraF
”?ecno rof gninrom eht ni nuf elttil a evah I t’naC“
.erif thguac hctip eht sa seye s’nirihS ni delkraps semalF
eripmE naisreP ythgim eht def srobal esohw esoht ot htgnerts gnitnarg ,tsevrah eht fo dog eht saw eH
,eadagrasaP eht fo rewoT etihW eht nekrad dluow edahs sti suomrone os eert elgnis a morf devraC
diarfa eb ot gnihton s’erehT
.esolc ni denael nirihS ,daeherof s’aetnaP no rufdaeh dekaos-retaw fo pom eht edisa gnihsurB
”.tnemom a tsuj tiaW“
spahrep ,sutats hgih fo seno—
”.nwo ruoy sa mialc won uoy taht ytic emas eht delur ecno elpoep yM .demhsaH ma I“
.pihstruoc ticat rieht ni tnemecnavda dnuofwen siht no tcelfer ot rewopniarb eraps eht dekcal aetnaP
.ria daed eht ni llits yltcefrep
.liah dezis-aep yb dednuop yltneloiv saw ruf rieht
.tsaf flesreh dloh ot debrevir kcils eht otni
sropav cilohocla htiw
.esoprup ruo fo lufdnim ,rehtona eno htiw tneserp tis ot su diA
”.tnecs railimafnu na gniraeb emoc uoY
”.aetnaP gninrom dooG .arahshsarA
tsoc eht si yltcaxe tahW“
.gnibbir lufyalp htiw etelper tiebla
,htiw uoy tneserp ot egnellahc tahw wonk lliw eH
”?sdog dlo eht gnivlovni gnihtemos spahreP“
syad ytriht rof nus eht ni deruc evah taht setad morf edam knird suoiruc a s’tI .rumuhkla hkirat siht llac htuoS eht fo sexof cennef ehT“
,reh dniheb htrof dna kcab dekcilf liat reH
.lacarac desumeb eht ot denrut aetnaP
,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb
”?thgir ,oot taht gniees er’uoY“
,iotanahtA na tey ton er’uoy fi nevE“
.yks sseldne na revo thgirb wolg srats gnilkniwt ,srevir eht fo dne eht tsap tuo taht draeh ev’I“
.spil kcalb-tej s’lacarac eht fo egde eht ta tperc elims a
.sdeed doog dna ,sdrow doog
,aidehM fo dnaltraeh lairepmi eht morf ton saw ehs hguohT
.pu gnitius elihw ecnocs nori detsur a ni yldrazahpah detnuom hcrot dekcarc a detcepsni drapoel ehT .dias aetnaP
”?uoy t’nevah ,ti fo draeh ev’uoY“
”?nirihS ,ti si woH“
dleif nepo eht ssorca aetnaP detrocse nirihS ,lwahs s’namow dlo na ekil sdaeh rieht revo kaolc foorpretaw reh gniwarD
htob er’uoy ekil war sedih ruoy nat ll’I
.dne rieht ees dluoc uoy erofeb tes dna esir dluow nus eht
.elpmet eht ot ssecca tcerid dekcolb taht
.drawpu desuffid sropav enivid eht sa mednat ni detalid slipup riehT
llaw enots eht no swalc sih derettap-rettip eh ,resolc gnimoc ylwolS
”.ecnegilid eud s’eno gniod tsrif tuohtiw edam eb ot thguo tnemtsevni oN“ .deksa nirihS
.sredluohs delcsum-llew revo gnirettulf kaolc htolclio reh
.droc pmeh fo htgnel a htiw tsiaw reh dnuora ti deruces sregnif suoretxed s’drapoel ehT
.tcudeuqa dnuorgrednu na—
srenommoc era siragaS“
nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI
.drawrof flesreh leporp ot swalc dednetxe reh gnisu ,tnemom a tub rof hcae no deregnil ehS
ev’uoy tseb eht siht sI .drapoel a er’uoY“
,htaerb peed a koot aetnaP
senots fo paeh degnarra ylluftra na fo erom won saw tahw tub—
.segdes dna snref yb nekatrevo-flah
.āhnA eht tcetorp ot uoy rof yarp eW .elpmeT rennI eht fo droL ,adzaM aruhA“ .noitacovni dercas eht reffo ot noitagilbo reh saw ti ,tsegnuoy eht sA
”.eno siht no tfel hctip elttil a llits s’ereht kniht I
.deniwtne spil htiw esor yeht sa skeehc s’lacarac eht depsarg ehs ,ylpeed gnihtaerB .nirihS htiw ssik tsrif reh gnirahs yb
”?tuo ti epocs annaW .stnaercsim wef a tsuj ylbaborp s’tI“
.lodi eht erofeb hsid gnireffo na no ti gnicalp
.mlap etad a fo knurt eht tsniaga thgilnus fo hctap ylenol a ot revo reh deggard nirihS ,kcen reh fo ffurcs eht yb reh gnibbarG
.serugif dedaeh-lamina fo skaolc eht denroda fael dlog fo sehctap dehsarht-dniW
.wets ruoy hsinif dluohs uoY“ .eseehc drah dna
dog eht fo lodi na ta decnalg ehs sa seye reh dellor aetnaP ”.si
.sllaw dedduts-toor nopu thgil elbeef tsac gniliec eht ni detnuom latsyrc suomrone nA
.dneirf on era uoy tey dna
.htraeh eht morf gninnur epip a yb detaeh
ylbaborp…shpargotcip er’yeht kniht I“
”.drapoel gnuoy ,hguone riaf—
elpmeT rennI eht fo mutcnas tsepeed eht fo edistuo ecitcarp sti edabrof partaS ehT .luos eht stpurroc ti ,esle lla evobA
.tsriht gnigar s’drapoel eht dehcneuq eniw eniregnat deganu eht ,teews dna dloB
”!gnorw s’gnihtemoS“
”?eltit a naht erom eb dluoc
.ylluferac sdrow reh esohc ehs sa llef neht ,esor—
.romra s’aetnaP pu gnirehtag elihw detuohs nirihS
sedirts sih gnihctam ylsuoicsnocnu flesreh dnuof aetnaP
.ediw tnew seye s’aetnaP ”—tub-B“  ”.etuor
.sdeew retaw gniworg-tsaf yb llitsdnats a ot dekohc hcae
tnatsni na rof sbir sih fo egde prahs eht desopxe eH
”,retlehs dnif dluohs ew ,reverof tsal ot siht ekil d’I sa hcum
drawnwod ti delgna nirihS ,bulc-erif a ekil hcrot eht gnitaerT
,lacarac eht naht ylthgirps sseL
”kraM s’partaS ehT“
”.yadot degnellahc eb ot tes er’uoY“
,srae reh detluassa esion dnuorgkcab tnatsnoC
rafuoliN tnavres rieht ,ybraeN
.]sehctulc s’demhsaH
.ni stes yad eht fo taeh eht erofeb ,gnivom teg s’teL“
,enitsetni xyro deird-nus fo htgnel a yb hgiht reh tsniaga tsaf dleh esac htolclio na ni dnuora gnilffuR
.smrof ynam ni emac ti hguoht ,egnellahc eht gnirud
.deilper aetnaP
.lla ta gnihton saw ereht ,neht dnA
.nadamaH fo ytic laicnivorp eht desivrepus taht selbon eht fo eno
truoc layor eht rof sdoog gnikees sredart wef a ylno taht wenk aetnaP .deksa nirihS ”?flesruoy rof htuoS eht ees dna og ot tnaw reve uoy dluoW“
?huh ,sdnuorg gniniart eht ta seert sselhcnarb fo dleif eht no emit erom elttil a dneps ebyaM“
.ruf fo stfut dnarre yna tuo htooms
.emas eht lla srenommoc tub—
.suoregnad oot eb ll’ti tbuod I“
”.dnal siht ot regnarts on ma I
siragaS eht ,sgnaf reh gniraB
.seye reh ni gnisir sduolc mrots ,dias nirihS
.htraeh ylimaf eht ediseb ronoh fo ecalp a ni tes ,amoaH
,aqrahsla fyas a debbarg aetnaP  ”.tsisni
”.laed taht ekat ll’I…mH“  .dekoj ehs
.aibuN fo tlas dna yrovi hcir eht morf eripmE eht detarapes taht
nus gnitaeb eht sa erusaelp htiw
.tcere gnidnats erew kcen s’rehtom reh fo epan eht gnola selkcah eht taht deciton ehs ,gninworF
.ruf reh tsniaga tuat dnuob reggad dehtaehs a delaever hgiht renni reh fo hsalf suoitatrilf A
”.flesruoy niarts ot uoy tnaw t’nod I .ysae ehtaerb tsuJ“  ”.emit txen
draknat eht fo edis eht tsniaga swap reh demmurd ylsuovren aetnaP
detrad wap reH .dias aetnaP
sduolc revlis-htoomsretaw htaeneb detaerter ylluf nus ehT
.stnilf dlehdnah fo riap a tuo dellup nirihS
”,rehtoM ,loop dercas a sa raelC“
.etuor cinecs eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,krad denrut dlrow ehT
.semehprom eht erimda ot denrut eh sa
.azrim ,skram thgie dessap sah laidnus ehT“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,rihsmahs reh fo edalb devruc eht ekiL
.noillats gnigrahc a ekil drawrof flesreh delruh ehs erofeb egaruoc reh gnirehtag
,knab rehto eht no gnitteuoriP
ydob reh ni elcsum yreve
uoy dnimer I deeN“
.senots revir neewteb sessaverc eht ni esahcrup dnif ot teef reh no swalc deppit-reppoc eht desu ehs
s’elpmet eht deciton ehs sa
”.emit ni ereht teg ot tuctrohs eht esu ot deen ew os
.wajkcol yb detcilffa erew ehs hguoht sa gnixelf
.tserkcab s’riahc eht ni tils worran a hguorht gnikop
evah nac uoy ,cigam doolb htiW“
epacse nirihS dna aetnaP[ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.diuqil nedlog htiw sdraknat eznorb eerht dellif demhsaH
?tuo deffup os taoc ruoy tog s’tahW“
rof…taht rebmemer ot evah ll’I“
.gnihcleb ylsselemahs erofeb eveels trihs sih htiw ffo elzzum sih depiw eH
”.efil lanrete fo taht…wotseb tonnac adzaM aruhA neve taht rewop
kcinnikinnik elttil a evah I
,sthguoht doog fo ytissecen eht fo su dnimeR
.etag tnorf eht hguorht dessap yeht sa ezeeuqs rednet a mlap reh evag lacarac ehT
”.ti hguorht gniwolp naht troffe ssel raf sekat revir a ssorca gnioG“
.yltfos delims avraF ”.enola sdog eht ot terces taht evael eW
.elbat maebnroh eht ssorca morf rethguad reh ta gnicnalg elihw
,wob etilop a retfA
”.ti deen ll’uoy tbuod I hguoht…edalb ruoy tegrof t’noD
gniraelc eht hguorht detarebrever palcrednuht suonimo na ,ecnatsid eht nI
.rehtegot āhnA eht sdloh taht evisehda eht era yehT“
noziroh eht gnola raf os dehcterts taht htuoS eht ssorca snavarac dednammoc zefaH fayS dias rehtom yM“
”.uoy morf neddih tpek sah partaS eht htym a si tI“
wob a evag lacarac eht
.roolf eht otno hcamots reh fo stnetnoc eht deitpme ehs sa taorht reh dehcrocs eliB
,yrgnuh era stsaeb ynam erehw dlrow a nI
sa…mM“ .meht kootrevo edahs elihw
,drawrof delppot aetnaP  ”.txen semoc
.elkcuhc a htiw deilper nirihS ”,qamha ,esruoc fO“
,nwonknu yleritne
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.thgieh lluf reh ot pu werd ehs sa
ebor nenil htgnel-elkna na ni xnyl a—
tirips eht gniknird
.seilil retaw gnimoolb delbmeser taht ngised a htiw denrettap
gnidnal teef reh
.elzzum reh dnuora swap reh gnippuc ,detuohs nirihS
.stnemrag dekaos reh nopu llef
ekil eb ot rovalf eht dnif I
.meht dnuora egailof eht hguorht
.tip hsibbur a otni gnillaf senob dekcarc-rehctub ekil
.snordluap redluohs sih dnuora deniamer elprup nairyT evitcnitsid fo ecart A
.hteet dettirg hguorht delahxe dna swap reh dehcnelc ehs sa detsiwt elzzum s’nirihS
“ .flah ni ecnetnes txen reh decils ylnaelc llac gnitam gnicreip s’gorfllub A
”.stidnab ot tsol saw ograc fo thgiew lekehs elgnis a ton ,edalb sih yb detcetorP
.skcor eht eganam t’nac
”?til snocaeb esoht era…erA“  ”?eeS“
”!sruoy ekil htgnerts gnivah dnim t’ndluow I“
.snoitidart s’eripmE eht ot noitoved reh ni sselesaec saw xnyl eht
.decitonnu ssap ll’ew erus m’I .daor tneicna eht no seye ynam eb t’now erehT“
”.aetnaP ,oot uoy evol I“
,evals citsemod a ecnO
”,nirihS ,uoy evol I
sllaw enots otno thgil gnirekcilf werht ehs ,tfola hcrot gnizalb eht gnidloH
nekops sah partaS ehT“
”—emit eht rebmemer uoy od ,hcihw fo gnikaepS
,skcor kcils eht ssorca ecnad ot ytiliga larutan reh desu nirihS
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
.deilper aetnaP ”.tseb eht spahreP“ 	 ”?thgir
”?kniht uoy od tahw ,onnud I“
”.nwod yaw eht lla snrub nus tresed eht fo tirips eht taht uoy nraw dluohs I hguohtla
erofeb sdnomaid tucnu ekil gnimaelg skeehc reh no stelpord retaw ,htmraw eht rof lufetarg saw ehS
.elgna eerged-ytriht tnerever eht dehcaer ehs litnu
nadamaH fo spotfoor elit-dum eht ta gnicnalg
dehcaorppa demhsaH sa srae reh ni tnemom a rof gnignir spetstoof gniohce
”?meht tegrof I dluoc woH .esruoc fO“
,ylkciuq tuo lles ll’eH
.sreh tsniaga dehsurb spil s’nirihS
?gnihtyna ees uoy oD“
.elzzum s’avraF fo egde eht ta dekeep elims thgils A ”.dooG“  ”.won
?eadagrasaP eht ot thgiarts ,oS“
”?tuo sdnif rehtom ym fi tahW“
.reh no pu gnivig t’nsaw lacarac ehT
.tnemngissa ruoy etatcid llahs
.yawa etalp reh gnivohs erofeb—
,retaw fo wolf ydaets a meht htiw thguorb ydaerla dah snosaes gnignahC
”.kaolcdlog a fo espmilg thguac tsuj I erows I
.taorht reh ni decnad lworg tnanoser a elihw
”,tra krad taht fo sterces eht sdraug ylesiw partaS ehT“
.teef reh dehsaw xnyl eht
regnarts eht dna aetnaP neewteb flesreh desopretni
.pis ylsuoituac lacarac eht devresbo ehs elihw
rednet s’nirihS yb derussaer yltnatsni saw dna daeh reh desiar ehS
.sdap wap reh tsniaga looc latem eht
.plug a koot eh elihw dedecer dna deglub taorht s’xnyl eht ,syawedis elzzum sih gnitliT
”,htym fo dnik emos gnitnuocer
rehtom reh erofeb rood eht tuo dekcud aetnaP
?noisacco siht fo ecnatropmi eht fo
.nirihS fo tnorf ni reh ssarrabme niaga ecno dluoc
”.uoy htiw srats esoht ees ot evol d’I“
”.hguone riaf ,mM“  .deilper aetnaP
”.sgniK fo gniK eht fo yaw eht si sihT
,nopaew reh fo tlih depparw-rehtael eht drawot gnitrad waP
.seenk reh ot llef ehs sa ratla eht gnihctarcs swalc
,seenk reh ta yltaen denetsaf cinut a yb derevoc saw ydob rewol reH
dehcaer dah riap eht ,maerdyad ymaets ylralucitrap a fo tuo deppans drapoel eht emit eht yB
enotsdnas fo erutcurts tneicna na ,sevlesmeht gnitacilppus āhnA eht fo eno fo elyts eht ni demroF
.ti delur ohw esoht nopu ytilativ gniwotseb dna
.elzzum reh otni ykrej raob dliw fo knuh a gnippop erofeb
,elbat eht fo egde eht no swalc derucinam reh demmurd ylsuovren avraF
tey railimaf wohemoS
.erif telracs htiw thgirb gniwolg ’seye‘
”?uoy era ,deirrow ton er’uoY
.slipup renni reh morf drawtuo detaidar taht htmraw ykoms a ,seye rebma reh ni dewolg eriF
.enutrof doog rof rehtegot yarp lla su teL“
,romra reh fo seceip regral eht ffo deppirts nirihS
ylsuovren dennacs aetnaP
.pirg eht dnuora depparw ti sa tsuj pmil og ot ylno
.eugnot neklis a htiw dias demhsaH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.sllaw s’elpmet eht ni semoh rieht edam dah taht serutaerc elbatnuocnu fo gnihctarcs dna gniyrrucs eht dna llafniar fo erutxim a
.taerht derepsihw a ekil htaehs eht morf eerf gnidils edalb delio eht
ymene on saw ereht ,gnorts dnasuoht-net ymra na yb dedleiW
.reed wollaf a gnisahc sretnuh gnitciped gnivargne enif htiw denroda saw drabbacs stI
.gard eziminim ot syawedis flesreh denrut ehs sa denrub shgiht reH
.unem eht no kcab reed wollaf deuqebrab tup sah najiB draeh I“
”?era eseht kniht uoy od tahW“
,yrrow t’noD .enabneh elttil A“
.egelivirp niatrec a detirehni ev’uoy ,htrib ruoy fo eutriv yB“
”.emit siht tegrof yletelpmoc t’ndid I ?eeS“
”,em htiw emac uoy fI“  	”.yks
.tnemrag klis eht fo egnirf eht denroda sesor deird fo nrettap a ,nosmirc hcir deyD
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
elihw ,steparap eht gnola dellortap romra rehtael dedaf-nus ni seirtneS
.dehsinomda rafuoliN ”,snoitidart eseht ronoh yltcirts tsum iotanahtA erutuf A
āhnA yreve taht wenk aetnaP
ecnerever ruo ni
”kraM s’partaS ehT“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
delaeh yletaidemmi saw gnissorc revir eht yb deniatsus oge reh ot dnuow ynA .smets siri hguot dnuora delruc yeht sa gnilbmert swap ,ruf reh htaeneb dehsulf aetnaP
.ecnalg tnatiseh a derahs nirihS dna aetnaP  ”.navarac
”.rasen hemyehg ruoy dehcuot ylerab ev’uoY .aetnaP ,pu nihC“  2 fo 1 traP
.doolb dellips ylhserf fo euh eht elbmeser ot
.yks eht ssorca decnad stlob gninthgil elihw
.eadagrasaP eht ot
.tnerruc eht fo htgnerts lluf eht tsniaga drawrof pets suoudra tsrif reh koot ehs sa maerts gnigar eht tsniaga tsaf reh dleh sevlac lufrewoP
.sesunis reh ni gniregnil rodo teews-ylkcis a gnivael
.ecafrus derramnu-esiwrehto eht ni sehctarcs peed lareves raen
.htap rieht morf hsurb evisurtni fo stib raelc ot
.tsaef gnineve eht rof eiressitor a no skcud lareves detsaor-wols kooc a
.spitregnif reh hguorht degrus htmraw sa
.evirra uoy ecno uoy ees lliw partaS ehT
,fayS eht fo eno htiw deniart uoY
,siht tuoba sthguoht dnoces evah ot gnitrats m’I“
.knab rehto eht ot elddap dluoc ehs erofeb maertsnwod raf reh peews dluow retaw eht niatrec tsomla saw ehs
.pihsredael rof uoy ot kool lliw āhnA eht taht snaem sihT .ylimaf layor
.dekram eb ll’uoy woh dna erehw swonk elpmeT rennI eht ylnO“
dna…syaw rieht uoy hcaet nac I“
.yratubirt eht fo retnec eht hguorht gninnur—
,elims yls a htiw dias nirihS
”.epip ym kcap ot ekil d’uoy fi tfel
,hteet reh gnittirG
uoy fi ssorca edaw tsuJ“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”!won tuoba thgir scitaborca ruoy evah ot evig d’I tahW“
ot sffur keehc reh hguorht eugnot debrab reh gnikorts rehtom reh devlovni setir eht fo etirovaf tsael reH
,retaw tlemwons ni tsub reh ot pu desremmi gnieb morf gnirevihS
.reilrae ecneserp sti rof gnikcehc ton rof flesreh desruc ehs ,mrala htiw gninediw seyE
”?sruoy ekil racs a yb dekram eb I lliW“
.knalf s’drapoel eht gnola wap reh dehsurb yltbus ehs sa pu gnikrep stfut rae reh ,dekniw nirihS ”.decitonnu
.daeh reh dewob aetnaP ,eugnot reh gnitiB
,rihsmahs reh rof dehcaer wap gnireviuq s’lacarac ehT
.won yb maerts eht nwod ecnatsid riaf a ylbaborp saw tI
.dedda rafuoliN ”.yaw eht si hcuS“
.egdelwonk hcus fo eulav eht ot derapmoc ronim si tsoc ehT“
.retteb od tsum uoY“
dnuof eb nac seirots sih fo eroM
,dnuorg eht otno tsrif-ecaf despalloc nirihS
.rebas ythgim eht tsniaga dnats dluoc taht reviR sudnI eht ot alusnineP naklaB      eht morf
.ytnuob a hcus erised dluow sutats ruoy fo iotanahtA na yleruS .rovaf rieht htiw semoc taht rewop eht uoy nopu wotseb
”?edis rehto eht ot ti ekam uoy fi ssik a tuoba woH“  ”.nirihS
”.stops thgir eht htiw nrob saw I esuaceb tsuj modsiw dercas htiw deubmi ton m’I“
.navarac gnidart a ni ekats gnikat naht tnemtsevni rednuos a si tI
.dehctaw gnieb fo gnileef suoicinrep eht ekahs etiuq t’ndluoc ehS
”!dewollof gnieb er’ew fi ees ot emit evah t’nod eW !ti nmaD“
detinu era ew ,erutluc dna noigiler ni esrevid era ew hguohT
”,etarbelec ot gnihtemos
,ratla eht htaeneb morf raj yalc suomrone na gniwarD
.enirhs eht htaeneb evocla delesihc a morf eremhsac hcir fo nevow sgur-
.seye lezah sih ni thgilerif eht fo noitcelfer eht ylno thguac aetnaP ,delaecnoc ecaf dedooh sih htiW
”,retfa nrob saw I“
,drawrof dereggats ehS
,gninrom dooG“   .dias aetnaP
”.iotanahtA eht fo
”.emas eht lla s’ti fi ,tniap-ruf elpmis referp d’I“
ekat…wonk uoy ,dluoc eW“
htym a fo ssel yllaer si ti hguohT“
uoy trocse ot ereh si nirihS taht esnes I“
.elpmet eht fo shtped eht drawot dedaeh eh sa
”?ti dluow won ,neht egnellahc a fo hcum eb t’ndluow tI“
”.evael uoy erofeb tirips ruoy esnaelc dluohs uoY
.seilleb lluf ruo rof sknaht evig ew
,secitcarp fo egavas tsom dna tsekrad eht saw tI
,evoba sdoG“ .noitapicitna htiw pu desnet ehs sa traeh s’drapoel eht hguorht tohs gninthgil fo tlob A .ezag
.ria dehcrap eht otni gnitaropave
”,semit lla ta em no eno peek I“
”,tnaem I tahw ton s’taht wonk uoY“
.deirrac iotanahtA yreve ylraen taht edalb devruc a htiw drows trohs eht
drawrof flesreh tlit ot liat ralucsum reh desu ehs
’latrommI‘ taht uoy dlot I fi tahW“
ti esu ot ytud ruo si ti dna
”.adzaM aruhA naht retaerg ecrof on si erehT“
.meht evoba sduolc yvaeh eht hguorht ekorb taht thgilnus fo sehctap delppad eht ni revlis dehsilop sa thgirb demaelg tI
.aesuan fo evaw a htiw emocrevo ylneddus saw aetnaP ,pis a gnikat retfa stnemoM
.moor eht fo dne rehto eht ta kcalb hctip otni ffo dehcterts ratla na
”.ytiliga ruoy rof srednow seod selop neewteb gnipaeL
seye sih dnuora ruf eht detfihs tnemgip enimrac elihw
.enivid eht fo kraps a saw meht neewteb ria eht ni dednepsuS
,arahshsarA na sa ecalp reh denrae d’ehs woh fo rednimer a sa devres ti ,ruf fo dioveD .sredluohs erab reh gnola hcnarb eert gnirewolf a ekil gninnur
.llah eht otni deppets draugydob lacarac suoegrog reh sa deddon aetnaP  ”?drapoel gnuoy
elzzum s’drapoel eht ssorca decar mrala fo noisserpxe nA
eht fo hcnarb tedac a era eW“
”.ega fo emac I nehw em ot tneserp ot egnellahc tahw wenk eh sa tsuj
.kniw a htiw deilper aetnaP
”!won tuoba thgir ti esu dluoc I
egdirb a neeb ecno dah tahw ssorca gnipeews
.oga sraey ynam dnammoc s’avraF rednu spoort fo lavirra eht yb deerf neeb dah ehs
erofeb roolf elpmet eht fo enots dloc eht dehcuot ylerab dah teef riehT
”,noos erehwyna gniog eb t’now ew ekil skooL“
.remrofrep gnilevart a fo yhtrow
”?tuo dennalp etuor ruo evah uoy oD“
racs gnitsiwt eht esacwohs ot hguone tsuj denrut avraF
.nwonk eb eman ruoy teL“
,lavorppa ticat reh gnilpuoc a evag dna
sknar eht gninioj fo yhtrow s’ehs fi ees ot
.elzzum reh otni nikseniw a fo tuops eht detlit nirihS
,ni su secalp doolb ruo noitisop eht morf epacse on si erehT
.tsisni uoy ecnis ,drows ym ekat osla ll’I tuB“
.ruopnwod laitnerrot a otni
,efas yltcefreP ?eeS“
.pintac dna hrrym htiw dednelb
”?uoy llet tsuj partaS eht t’naC“
.elttob yalc ybraen a morf retaw fo ffauq gnol a htiw nwod rouqil eht dehsaw ehs ,spil reh gnitraP
”?cificeps erom eb uoy dluoC“
,draknat eht detpecca aetnaP  ”.eniw yenoh fo
.laihp nosmirc a depsarg eh sa ysatsce fo erutseg a ni desiar daeh
.sredluohs dna tsehc s’nirihS denroda zumroH morf edixo nori htiw wolley deyd romra rehtael delio ylhciR
”.ecnatropmi taerg fo gnihtoN“
.depsag drapoel eht
tanaq erutainim a hguorht maerts ydaets a ni enots enotsdnas derehtaew fo deb a ssorca dewolf retaw looc ,psirC
,kcab reh otno dellor aetnaP
.depihsrow ecno slacol eht mohw dog denword-flah eht
ti naem I :owt uoy ,netsiL“
senots fo deb a ssorca gniklaw yb
,slirtson reh gnits ot drawpu detfaw sropaV
”?osla meht yojne uoy dluow ,separg suonosiop fo lwob a eta nirihS fI“
”.tsrif ytilatipsoh ym reffo em teL“
”!raf taht ton s’tI !uoy evol—
erofeb puc revlis enif a otni eniw mulp fo erusaem egral a deruop avraF
dennirg lacarac eht ,teksab hcnul eht otni dekcut gab rehtael a edisni gnikeeP
”!pils uoy fi tuo uoy luah ot gab ym ni dor gnihsif a evah I