.yb gnissap ruo :I dna uoy tA
,”eraM deR ehT“    yojne esaelP
eno tub eno era owT
,tser eht htiw lleh ot ,ssertsid tegroF
,modeerf worrob ot dael ew yas yehT
eraM tsyhtemA yb meop a
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
rohtua yrruf dehsilbup-fles a si ohw
.ssenteews ytsum ruoy fo wodahs eht nI yats dluoc I taht hsiw os od I teY .yaw s’efil no
?regnad tahw ,yenoH
.llaf s’emit morf elats dna prahS
,eraM tsyhtemA yb
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.NGISLLAC htiw
,senips enip ot sevooh
?krad eht morf gniraer ,erugif a roF
”eraM deR ehT“ saw sihT         .enola
.setis yrruf rehto dna
ezarg uoy dna dehctal si etag eht woN
,erats naht erom on od yehT
.eb su tel ot modeerF
:tfos-pilc ,polc-pilC
.tnirp ni elbaliava snoitcelloc yrots tceles fo seipoc kcabrepap evah noos lliw dna
,eraM tsyhtemA yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tsol tnemom a ,enrobria dekcilf sevooH ,llats ton erad ,thgilf fo deeh ekat llahs eW
retirw noissimmoc dna
?erac swodahs eht kniht uoy – drawno gnilruC
,kral neddibrof taht ,kcaberab pu gnilbmarcS
?em htiw modeerf ruoy erahs ot sA dnik os eb d’uoy ,raed ym ,spahreP
,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
ytiniffAruF no krow rieht dnif nac uoY
lleweraf tsum dnA owt si
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot
hctaw uoy od ,snaorg thgiliwt nehW