.efil s'nalA devas I"
dehsulb lerriuqs ehT .dekrims nalA ".em
.noitats eht ni pots eht ot niart eht thguorb nalA
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.elbat s'nam dnoces eht htaenrednu derrits nooccar eht sa detnurg eH
.egairrac eht fo tser eht dna tnemtrapmoc gnivird eht neewteb rood eht ot nar regdab ehT
"?ti t'nia ,yad a eciwt thgir s'kcolc nekorb a
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.htaed sih ot ylsselrewop temmulp llub eht dehctaw eh sa
.nepo bac eht dna
,noitats eht ssorcA
,notweN rof daeh ot deraperp dna
enola esnes nommoc ot nwod ti gnivael
.ti denwo won ohw erianoillib eht fo aingisni eht gniraeb dna
eltsihw eht welb eh
,tihs ynnuf yna em evig uoy fi niart siht evird ylisae etiuq dluoc I
.dlot saw eh tahw tuoba tes ylgnigdurgeb nalA sa dehgual nooccar ehT ".ruf
egrahc eht fo ecrof eht dna flesmih pots ot tsaf oot gniog saw llub ehT
.tnemom a rof derednop nooccar ehT .dehgis eH ".ereht
,enog tsuj dah llub eht erehw yawrood eht ni doots ,kcohs ni dnuora nups nooccar ehT
,gniretne morf sehcaoc htruof dna driht eht ni sregnessap eht gnippots
,llaw egdirb eht tsniaga gnikaerb dna gnimmals kcab sih
.llub eht fo seye eht ni daed kool ot daeh sih gnisiar regdab eht
,daeh sih revo gnuws sleeh s'llub ehT
,hcaoc hpargotnap eht otni kcab devohs saw eH
si yrots s’yadoT dna
dne rehto eht ta evitomocol 68 ssalC eht ,tsartnoc yB
.erofeb derevocsid dah luaP rood gnittif-lli eht otni gnikcams
esiwrehto tub ,ssenkrad eht hguorht gnirutcnup sthgilliat der sti
,tellug sih tsniaga ylmrif erom desserp efink ehT ".ti
.retemodeeps sih dna kcart eht htiw yltnenamrep tcatnoc eye gniniatniam dna gnidnuop traeh
.sleeh revo gnilppot daeh
.esrow dah ev'I tuB .doog toN"
,s'0891 ylrae eht nI
.ecrof lluf ta no sekarb eht gnihsam
"ycacihte dna ytingid" sdrow eht
ynoga ni delrans eH
.seye sih erofeb eid nam dnoces a hctaw ot evah t'ndluow eh os ecipicerp egdirb eht fo raelc daeh sih llup ot deganam knuks ehT
,dedulcni saw thgildaeh lartnec ralimis A
gniniart s'nalA
...I dna niart eht kcajih ot deirt srebbor ,lleW"
luaP "?ecaf sih ot mih llet dna dnuor' llorts uoy tuob' woh lleW"
,sekarb ycnegreme eht reggirt ot drah gniknaY
lufraF lacsaP yb
.lliw I naht dum ni derevoc retteb tol a kool ll'uoy kniht I ,tsenoh eb ll'I"
,kcab sih no talf eil mih pleh ot nwod denael luaP sa ynoga htiw gnihctiwt
.rabworc a htiw knuks a
.rof detarepo yltnerruc ti krowten eht fo sdeen eht ot dna rof tliub tsael ta erew eseht
.dleiffehS dna retsehcnaM neewteb detcurtsnoc ylsuoiverp
.evael ot ydaer tuoba er'eW"
,roolf eht no deniamer nalA
,stnaliassa rehto eht fo owT
,mih morf eno siht edih t'naC
,bac niart eht pu tes ot nageb nalA
,mih evas dna yrt ot tuo dehcaer knuks ehT
,nalA yb decnelis ylkciuq
,dnah rehto eht nO
.noitats eht ni tas sniart fo sesion gnizzif dna gnikcit eldi eht dna
.dnuorg eht ot llaf gnol
.worg ot nageb ecneitapmi dna noisnet eht hguohT
erom ecno nepo tsrub tnemtrapmoc s'revird eht ot rood ehT
,ralugna eht lla erob tI
.deddon dna dennirg ohw
tab a dna flow a
,taes s’revird eht dniheb morf debmilc nalA
.dlo sraey 9 tuoba ylno
,luaP egrahcsid ot niaga devirra srotcod ehT
.egaP ytiniffaruF sih no
enohpelet a erob neve tI
,ti fo ffo gnippihc tniap htiw retnuoc latem A
.enecs eht no devirra yllanif ecilop sa efil sih rof gnidaelp ,sdnah sih pu dleh dna rabworc eht deppord eH
.snroh sih ffo gnippans ,edis etercnoc eht dekcams daeh s'llub eht dna
.yad eht fo serutraped tsrif eht rof ydaer
.woleb dnuorg eht ot teef 911 eht yllufecarg llef dna
.dne raf eht ta bac gnivird a htiw hcaoc egaggul a dna
,deffatsnu saw dna doow fo ylpaehc edam saw tI
.koorB possolG eht revo detcurtsnoc
.515 503 gnieb taht
thgia'Y" .wodniw eht nwod dils dna rood bac eht ot deklaw dna pu tog nalA
seirujni rieht morf desuor
.ssalc gnikrow eht yb ylevisnetxe erom desu
,ni meht dewollof eH
.flesmih pots ot ksed eht htaenrednu wap sih tup eh hguoht
,draobni kcab flesmih gniluah dna skcar egaggab eht ta drah gnibbarg lerriuqs eht
.ekam oreh a ton seod niart a fo ffo htaed sih ot yug a gnikciK"
.mih llik tsuj t'ndluow srekcatta eht yhw nosaer on saw ereht
meht derewop hcihw rosserpmoc eht dna desaeler erew sekarb eht nehw
,deretne nemhcneh eht fo eno dna
.ylivaeh yrujni sih gniruovaf llits
tcudaiv eht fo edis eht revo gniylf
.mih derussa regdab ehT ".em
.dleifdaH otni yltaen edils ll'ew dna gnikarb trats neht
.detnap lerriuqs ehT "?ti si dab woH"
,ecnaraeppa sti fo sgnivigsim eht lla roF
.wap sih no stuc eht otni gud niahc llams eht sa ynoga ni tuo deliaw eh
.ti ot ycacihte dna ytingid a htiw eno
dne hcae ta bac a htiw enihcam egral yrev a saw tI
,swodniw gnikool-elbaresim ,egral owt erob niart eht fo sbac eht
ti fo pihsrenwo nekat ylgnigdurgeb dah taht ynapmoc eht fo
noitareneg moc-tod eht tius retteb ot snoitacifidom s'tI
.edisbus ot gnitrats tsuj ylno enilanerda s'luaP
.elzzum sih ssorca yaw sti gnittuc krims a
.nibac eht ssorca ta deralg gnieb saw eh erawa ,dedda eH ".wonk
,traeh fo tniaf eht ro
.redluohs s'dnabsuh sih otni ecaf sih deirub dna
.noitats ynit eht hguorht gnirettab dna gnirettalc erofeb
.egdirb eht fo edis eht revo mih gnillup
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.sdnuow efink dna sredwop ynnuf htiw krow morf emoh gnimoc tpek I esuac' boj reporp a teg I dednamed efiw yM"
,dum emos htiw doog kool ll'uoY" .dennirg eH ".erutuf
dias eb t'ndluoc emas ehT
,kcart eht morf yawa nrut ot stcnitsni sih thguof eH
,taes s'revird-oc ytpme eht otni gnirettab nooccar deraperpnu eht delruh ecrof sihT
,srevael fo eireganem a dna slaid eugolana ni derevoc
noissucrep s'kcolc eht ot tneminapmocca cidolem eht dedivorp taht sgnissih dna s’gnikcit niart detrossa eht
.dekrims regdab ehT
...eheH" .ekohc ot detrats eh esac ni gnihctiwt luaP
,egairrac eht fo renroc eht ot revo gninnur dna efink eht gnippord
,cimhtyhr a gnivig
,edis thgir eht ot ssorca gnulf neht
,regdab eht ot lerriuqs eht morf dekool retto ehT
,dekcol yllartnec ton ,detarepo regnessap erew srood esehT
yltnetrevdanI .ti gnibbarg
riahc eht ni elbatrofmoc flesmih gnitteg ,sgniraeb sih deniater nalA
,thgim gniniamer sih lla htiW
.no erew sthgil liat der eht taht kcehc ot bac raer eht ot kcab klaw dna rehtegot lla niart eht evael ot dah eH
.stekcit kcehc ot gnitrats dna
!efas er'uoY !luaP"
.smroftalp ytpme eht tuohguorht
,emit yna ta srood eseht fo yna nepo dluoc enoyna os
.s'esuops sih ot kcab neht
?yas ot gniog drahciR s'tahw doG"
,wodniw bac eht fo tuo morf esirnus eht otni yltnagele dils 68 ssalC eht sa ylgnignol derats eH
.daetsni knuks eht htiw edilloc ot llub eht gnisuac
erew 503 s'luaP dna nalA sa hcus sniart dna pu deppir saw dleifdaH tsap kcart eht
.ffuts ynnuf yna yrt t'noD"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,gnol eht edam nooccar eht ,liaw ot deunitnoc eh sA
.mottobdaorB ta pots t'noD"
.regdab eht dniheb hcaoc tsrif eht morf hguorht yaw rieht gnikam
.hhhhS"   .eromyna noitpo na ekil mees t'ndid siht ,taorht sih ot desserp efink a tlef eh nehw hguoht
,revel ekarb eht rof hcaer ot mih dlot
,cisum edulcni stiolpxe yrruf s’ohw
,tsal ta dias luaP ".evael
,daeh sih fo ekahs llams a htiW
.mih ta gnivaw ,lerriuqs gnuoy a
.won yb htiw decneirepxe saw nalA gnihtemos
.wal eht htiw skconk drah dna sevink gnivlovni yllausu ,snoitautis elbatrofmocnu dna ykcits ni roirp erom ynam
,niart eht otni deppets dna
.ngised s'0691 sti fo ciler a
.etuor siht desu taht sniart ylno eht fo emos
,ylper dluoc nalA erofeB
,moor eht deretne retto ralucsum yrev a dna nepo gnuws rood eht nehw detpurretni saw ecnelis ehT
.ecivres gniddew a ta dlihc gnivahebsim a ekil
.meht tsap gnilbmuts dna
.mih hguorht eciv niap fo stlob tub pu dnats ot deirt eH
.luaP ta pu dekool nalA
.did egatniv ralimis fo 68 ssalC eht sa tsuj edoc daeh eht erab ot desu dna denodnaba yal hcihw
.niart eht ssorca hcnual eht yb deniur saw kcab s'regdab ehT
.flesti fo dna ni aera retsehcnaM retaerG eht fo trap detalupop llew ylriaf a saw dna
.rehtona dehcaorppa yeht sa nwod kcab gnikcud neht
ni tahW" .gnihtyna naht erom tcnitsni no
daeherof htooms dna devruc esiwrehto na fo tuo gnikcits xob llams a saw erehT
.desolc saw daehdooW eht fo klub eht retfa gnol detcurtsnoc
,dekrims nooccar ehT ".erac t'noD"
.elbat elttil eht htaenrednu mih gnikconk
dne raf eht ta bac eht ot kcab knil ot selbac elttil fo mrof eht ni emac
.erom ecno degguh saw eh sa nalA ta revo kcab gnikool
ecrof dna dnuos gnirettab lacinahcem yrev a htiw
,efil no esael wen a saw yawliar eht tuB
emit eht fo kcart peek ot niart eht nwod gnikool ,dedda luaP ".sgniht
.dnE ehT .dekrims nalA
.nam elpmis a saw snilloC nalA
,s'02-dim sih ni regdab A
.yponac tsav s'noitats eht fo swolloh eht dellif hcihw
.ria eht ot pu hpargotnap ylredle na gnituorps driht s'ti
,ylthgit dnah sih gnidloh neht
.ecaf sih morf gnippird niap fo sraet
.redleiw s'efink eht fo eciov eht emac ".gnivird peeK
desioprop dna derettalc ti
.snoitats fo yteirav a tas dleifdaH dna retsehcnaM neewteB
.emit hguorht pu debmilc yeht sa
tros eht fo gnihtemos detcepxe dah nalA
,skcar lecrap latem eht fo eno otni
saw edam 503 dlo eht taht noitommoc tsav yllaer ylno ehT
,skcolc lacinahcem fo dnuos eht saw draeh eb dluoc taht lla dna
.evil ot teg uoy dna dleifdaH ot su teG
.mih dniw ot hguone tug sih htiw elbat gnivird eht tih llits tub
,ytitnedi laudividni sti saw gnirettel ykcits ni no kcutS
,noitats hcae tfel dah niart eht ecno niaga efink eht htiw mih netaerht ot gnivom bac eht ni rekcatta eht
.niart eht ot dettif ylevitcaorter saw taht
,relevart decneirepxeni eht roF
.knuks eht ot delley llub ehT "!pu mih kciP"
efil otni derednuht
,gniwohs roop sa nees eb ot spahrep saw noitomocol s'06 dna s'07 ,s'08 ,s'09 fo hsamhsim a elihW
.tnorf eht ni gnineppah saw tahw ot suoivilbo yllatot
,tcudaiv gnitniD eht pota tlah a ot dehceercs niart ehT
.sdworc llams eht ot eud ruoh hsur ta naht reisae ylluficrem saw erudecorp a hcus ,gninrom eht ni 52:5 tA .noitats eht fo tuo dellup nalA elihw draob ot deirt ydobon evresbo ot tuo daeh sih kcits d'eH
.mih dniheb gnimmals rood eht
.taes s'revird-oc eht tsniaga mih gnikconk dna tug eht ni mih gnittubdaeh ,dekcud ohw
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,mrif doots hcihw srood regnessap edis tfel eht tsniaga derettab saw regdab ehT
.ti fo egde eht ot esolc ylbanosaer ,mroftalp eht no gnitiaw enoemos ees dluoc eH
,s'nalA ot gnivom ezag sih
noitats eht ni eton fo niart rehto ehT
.niaga bmilc eht gnitrats ylidaets ,sruoh 00:00:50 ta
,yletanutrof ,saw tI
s'68 ssalC tsilaturb s'liaR hsitirB fo eno fo demrof ecivres yticretnI nA
,esuap gnol a saw erehT .detnurg
tniop siht ta saw tI
.srebmun lausu sti revo esaercni tnacifingis a saw MA6 tuoba ta elpoep 6 tuoba
.ereht er'ew neht dna gnitniD dna mottobdaorB tsuJ"
,rekcatta sih ta ecnalg a laets ot deganam dah nalA ,siht gniruD
tnatsidiuqe daerps erew yehT
duht citehtap a htiw gnidnal
”yrebboR dleifdaH ehT“:yojne esaelP
,noitats gnitniD ot nwod meht dewollof luaP
htron eht ot seninneP eht hguorht levart ot gnipoh sregnessap rof egnahcretni tnacifingis a
daeh sih fo kcab eht debbur dna
.daeh sih gnikahs ,deffocs luaP "...tffP" .dereffo nalA
.rehtegot owt eht gniknil epirts kcalb kciht a htiw
.roolf eht ot kcab delbmut dna
,draoba debmilc dah srelggarts tsal eht ecnO
srotom cirtcele egral sti looc ot desu snaf fo ssam eht dih
,snoitats owt txen eht ta spots ehT
”yrebboR dleifdaH ehT“
.tcudaiV gnitniD eht dessorc niart eht erofeb tnorf ot kcab morf teg ot saw nalp ehT
,yltneg gnikcit tas evitomocol ehT
,niart eht hguorht yaw sih ekam ot nageb retto eht
.tsal ta derettu retto ehT ".oreh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.segairrac eht fo edis hcae no srood 01 tuoba
,dniw erab eht ot nepo gnigniws dna gnignihnu ti
,edoc daeh tigid-ruof sti fo tnemecalper a dna
,retteb tib elttil a flesmih ecarb ot deganam dah dna
.niart rednarg eht fo raor gnicanem eht raen gnikam ton srotom dega s'ti
,dnim sih fo kcab eht ni ylkciuq saw tI
,hcaoc niart eht fo tuo mih gniworht ,tug s'nooccar eht ot kcik a dereviled eH .dekrims luaP ".lliw
gnitirw dna gnitiusruf
.repmuj kcalb egral a ni dalc nooccar elam a
,tfos dna yvruc lla ,retnec eht ni eno rellams ylthgils a dna
raor cinomed a dehsaelnu dna pu deloops eseht detavitca saw niart eht nehw dna
.ylsselhtaerb raen detsetorp eH ".pots
.noos hguorht ti ekam ll'ew ,ti tuhS"
.noitats mottobdaorB dehcaorppa niart ehT
.eye eht ni rehto hcae kool ot tnatculer htob riap eht
.kcalb eht otni knus niart eht
erob ti stnev ehT
,guh thgit a ni lerriuqs eht gnibbarg ,deirc eH
.dehcaorppa revird sti sa eow ni gnizzub dna gnissih ,ereht tas tI
.niart eht pu gnilbmuts erew llub egral a dna xof a ,erom owT
.rehtegot lla ti gnidloh stevir dna edis sti gnola stnev llams suoirav dna
,detcepxe d'eh naht elpoep erom erew ereht taht deciton eh
".enif od ll'uoY" .dehgual nalA ".sdnuow
sih koohs lerriuqs ehT
,elbissop sa yltneloiv sa depmud saw erusserp ekarb muucav eht fo lla sa
.thgis fo tuo nwod deppord renwo sti dna taorht eht morf xaler ot detrats edalb eht
."?eh dluohs neht ,elpoep ta sevink detniop gnikcuf evah t'ndluohs eh ebyam eid ot tnaw t'ndid eh fI"
,deb latipsoh a otni derrefsnart saw nalA ,ruoh eht nihtiW
.erutuf ruoy rof retsat elttil A
.esool gnilbbow saw rood eht dna
,niart eht fo tuo gniylf nem htob tnes
.wap thgir sih nepo tuc eh ,draoba kcab flesmih gniknay fo ecrof eht ni tuB
pots a ot semoc niart eht ,nottub eht sserp t'nod I fI" .denialpxe nalA ".noitnetta
siht fo elpmaxe emirp A
,noitats notweN deretne niart eht sA ".evil
daeh s'xof eht fo kcab eht gnibbarg
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.lavivrus ta ecnahc tseb sih saw emoctuo tseb eht meht evig ot gniyrT
gnikcit tnetopinmo riehT
,niart eht fo tnemele tsegnuoy eht saw reliart gnivird sihT
pu nevig evah ot demees srood regnessap eht no skcol eht fo eno deciton eh ,hcaoc hpargotnap eht hguorht devom eh sA
.gnihton saw tI" .daeh
,niaga deremmats luaP
tas taht sniart fo noitcelloc a morf emac
,desu llew-tsom eht saw egdirB ediuG
.oreh gib yM .oreh a er'uoY"
.saw s'nalA taht tnetxe eht ot ton hguoht
.em tsurT .lliw uoY"
.dnah tnanimod-tub-dednuow sih htiw os did eh ,tcnitsni no dna
.detnurg regdab ehT ".spahrep
.elbaresim ylrettu dekool ti ,yawa gnikalf dna dlo sraey
.erusopmoc niager ot deirt eh sa
,egairrac eht fo roolf eht no llef eH
yelsrettaH dna yeldoG
.wonk ll'yeht ro spots eht od ot evah I"
sniart eseht fo citoxe tsom ehT
.nwod wodniw eht gniggut dna mih dniheb rood eht gnisolc
.ruf ym fo tuo doolb hsaw ot evah t'now I dna niaga ylimaf ruoy ees ot teg ll'uoY
,noitats retsehcnaM tfel niart eht sA
.seldnah dna sehctiws ,snottub
noitats eht fo tuo niart eht dellup nalA
sniart retummoc nabrubus eht rof
.mroftalp ht4 eht no revo tas tinu elpitlum cirtcele 503 ssalC a saw
".em rof krow taht od ot uoy teg I fi em rof reisae tsuj s'ti
;selop thgil leets elttil morf delgnad skcolc noitats ehT
.tuo gnideelb t'nsaw taht eno eht ni emit siht
,delbmessa stnatabmoc eht ,nooS
.niaga denepo meht dniheb rood eht ,yelsrettaH tfel yeht sA
tsrif egairrac raer eht ot gnivom
,nalA rof gnuws eH
,gniyfirret ylevitisop saw krab sti
"?niart siht no enola saw I thguoht uoY“
.niart eht ot ti ekam scidemarap eht
yrc ot detrats eh erofeb ,riap eht neewteb dekool drahciR
,roolf eht no gniyl ydob gnisluvnoc s'nalA
.semit lla ta ecnetsixe deunitnoc sti ta dekcohs ylrettu kool niart eht gnikam htaeneb eno lanoitidda na htiw
.tekcar gniyfirroh a saw ti
krad llits saw yks ehT
edis eht nwod sepirts etihw wef a htiw emehcs tniap kcalb dna der hsirag a ni dettiftuo erew ,ot dehcatta saw ti niart eht fo emos htiw gnola ,tI
,sdrawrof gnicaf swodniw eerht dah bac hcaE
,enil eht no noitats tsewen eht saw sihT
,ecrof kaerb eht yb dnuorg eht ot nworht gnieb morf pu gnidnats tsuj erew
.ecnelis eht llif ot tpmetta on edam lerriuqs ehT
krab laruttug enot-owt gnikahs-retfar a gnivig niart eht
.rabworc s'knuks eht morf gniws a yb detcartsid regdab eht
,syawliar eht no raey a ynam tneps dah eh
emit tnecer erom a morf noitnevni na saw rettal ehT
.deeps ta os od ot ton
.elat siht ot ecnatropmi tsom fo eno eht saw
.mih erofeb luaP gniees
.elbac egatlov hgih eht gnihcuot pot no hpargotnap mra latem egral eht
"?taht saw kcuf eht
.8991 tsuguA fo ht02 eht saw etad ehT
tniop siht ta saw tI
,lufraF lacsaP yb
dnuos a ot detavitca metsys ekarb ycnegreme ehT
,drah gnihguoc erofeb ,delbmurg eH ".esrow
,deraeppa luaP nehw ffo tuc yltnetrevdani erew yehT
,gnitniD litnu nepo ediw rekcuf siht evael uoy
.gnidraob sregnessap yna dna
.ecnalubma eht ni nalA gninioj neht ,pu deretsalp dnah sih gnitteg
,dnoces a rof cinap ot rekcatta eht desuac hcihw dnuos gnignir duol a saw erehT
,skcart sih ni daed deppots lerriuqs ehT
,notweN ta mroftalp eht otno dna
gnirif nonnac a ot nika
taorht eht ni hcae gnikcik yltfiws regdab eht
.uoy morf niart siht revo ekat dna uoy llik ll'I rO" .yltrohs deredro eH ".mottobdaorB
"?uoy t'now ,esproc ydoolb ruoy otni dexim ssarg emos
ogol no-kcits kciuq eht yb ylno dednema erew skool s'tI
rorret ni etihw gniog
.tsal ta denialpxe eH ".efil
,bac tnorf eht ot niart eht fo htgnel eht deklaw eh sA
niart eht fo sedis ehT
sehcaoc regnessap fo tes dehctamsim a htiw sreffub eht ta
,pu taeb tahwemos llits saw ydob sih sa dat a detnurg luaP
.ti wot dna emoc ot evah yeht dna
.emit tsal tuo krow t'ndid tI"
,roolf eht ot deppord dna knuks eht fo eerf dellup nalA
,rehtegot ecnelis
.enil eht no pots txen eht
,degnahc dna detfihs stigid lacinahcem rieht fo 6 lla rednuht tnelis raen a fo odnecserc eht nI
ni tas riap ehT   .sruoh wef a rof mih htiw yats ot dewolla gnieb luaP
dnah deidoolb sih gnildarc
.spahrep reredrum A
.emit sti fo yldediced saw 503 ssalC eht fo bac ehT
.em tsurt ot uoy dlot I"
.deksa namefink ehT
nooccar dna knuks eht dna
emit 'setunim 21 tuoba ni derevocsid eb dluow sa
,gnineppah saw tahw fo erawa erew seitirohtua eht fI
nibac s'draug eht fo tuo debmilc luaP
,srood dna swodniw ralugnatcer ynit fo ssam a erob
.6 mroftalP nopu tas
.spmal thgirb owt htiw
.mih evas dluoc gnihton tub ,egdirb leets eht ta yltneloiv dewalc dna demaercs eH
.dleiF yrewolF sa hcus snoitats ot emoh osla saw ti
.noitats eht ssorca 68 ssalC eht morf degreme liaw gnilwoh gninefaed taht taht
,denialpxe lerriuqs ehT "...I
,lworg a htiw nroh niart eht rof dehcaer nalA
,sepip eht otni dekcus gnieb ria fo dnuos gnol a yb dewollof
".rof enod eb ll'ew ,7 yb dleifdaH ot teg t'nod ew fI"
,ffo naelc deppans rood diaS
rebmun rieht yb denedlobme ,eslup gniohce
.siht hctaw ot gniog er'uoy ,on hO"
.pleh ot luaP no tnuoc ylirassecen t'ndluoc eh gnizilaer ylkciuq nalA
.sseltiurf dna feirb saw
bac eht ot tseraen rood regnessap eht nepo gnigniws
,drohc pots ycnegreme eht rof gnihcaer
.ecnelis tcefrep raen ni tas noitats yawliar yllidacciP retsehcnaM
,srood regnessap eht fo eno otni nibac eht ssorca yltneloiv gnuws eh nehw erudecorp gnippots eht ot noitaretla eht fo erawa emaceb luaP
,rekcib dna eugra ot detrats sregnessap wef ehT
.dloc tuo mih gnikconk
,hcaoc raer eht sdrawot deunitnoc dna egairrac eht ni esoht detrela eH
.feilebsid ni daeh sih koohs nalA ".uoy
.wodniw sih ta kconk a gniviecer flesmih dnuof nalA nehw tniop siht ta saw tI
,noitom otni eldnurt ot detrats 503 eht sA
.deplug regdab ehT
stfihs gninrom ylrae eht kniht llits eh seoD" daeh sih koohs nalA ".desaelp ton s'ybbuH" .delbmurg lerriuqs ehT ".eyA" .dekrims nalA
,tnemtrapmoc draug s'hcaoc hpargotnap eht morf eltsihw s'luaP htiw dna
,yawliar cirtcele daehdooW cirotsih eht fo trap gniniamer ylno eht ,possolG dna dleifdaH rof dnuob saw ecivres ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw
.niart dlo roop eht fo gnittifeb leef ton did
.nooccar eht yb tniop-efink ta deppots si tub ,htrof gnireggats ,seirc luaP "!oN"
,tuo teg elpoep wef a gnivresbo
.sgniht
.edisni retupmoc latigid ynit a dna
,noitats eht otni niart eht desae regdab eht sA
edis egdirb eht tsniaga pmil yletelpmoc tnew ydob dednuow s'knuks ehT
?uoy did ,thguac teg ot ton yaw eht fo tuo gnikcud tsuj saw I kniht yllaer t'ndid uoY"
,nalA rof hctih a tuohtiw tsomla ffo tnew
.elbat eht ot tcapmi eht morf gnikcah dna gnihguoc
,pu doots dna ssenerawa deniag yllautneve luaP tub
egdirb eht tsniaga demmals kcab s'knuks eht
"?gnol os 'nikat s'kcuf eht tahW"
,dekcinap nooccar ehT
,gnol sehcaoc ruof saw tI
,hguone esolc er’eW“
nopaew fo dnik emos rof dnuora gnikool nalA ,pukcab tuohtiw saw eh gnizilaer llub eht
.yawliar nredom a morf tnaw thgim eno selpicnirp ngised nredom ylevissergga dna keels
"?oreh a er'uoy tahT" .delbmurg luaP "...swen
.noitnetta yap ot em secroF"
,nalA no tpel dna denrut llub ehT
"?ew t'noW" .delbmurg nooccar ehT ".noos
.nwo s'llub eht hguorht deppils sregnif sih woh saw efil s'knuks eht devas taht gniht ylno eht tub
”yrebboR dleifdaH ehT“ saw sihT
.dehcatta saw ti hcihw fo egairrac eht koohs hcihw
"?ay t'ndid eno siht ylrae pu toG ?luaP
.dias dah nalA tahw etupsid ot mees t'ndid rekcatta eht hguoht
.sgniht eseht no pu taeb gnitteg em fo seramthgin gnivah speek eH .peY" "?seno ygdod eht era
,pu nalA detfil knuks ehT
ecrof lluf ti gnimmals dna
"?uoy t'nera ,retsam uf-gnuk elttil
,mih ta degrahc llub eht sa
,draug s'niart eht was dna revo dekool eH
.nalA ta kcab deralg eH
.traped ot eud saw ti nehw
.dezilanif saw ssecorp eht elihw tseuqer s'rotcod eht ta tsrif moor eht gnivael drahciR htiw
.htaerb sih rednu derettum eH ".gnihton
.mroftalp sih fo dne eht ta langis eht gnikcehc dna
evoba morf gnilgnad selbac lacirtcele lahtel eht morf zzub llud a
"?uoy ot deneppah htrae no tahw sdog hO
wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.flesti niart eht fo tnorf eht no sthgil eht dna sehcaoc eht ni gnitaeh dna gnithgil eht no gninrut
,skrow gniht siht woh tuo dekrow ev'I
edis hcae ta seno egral owt
.selbuort sih rof tug eht ni dewoble saw dna
...llew haeY" .dehgual luaP ".emit
,yawkcart dna stniop eht revo noihsaf ylniagnu na ni
xob testuo na ssorca
yltfos derettalc stigid lacinahcem rieht
...swen 'nikcuf eht no eb ll'I
.egairrac niart eht fo tuo mih desae dna rehcterts a otno nalA tup yehT
dnah gnideelb sih gnihctulc luaP
,tnelis deniamer nalA
,edisni esactius sih gnicalp dna rood s'revird eht gninepo
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.pots t'nod I fi gnorw s'gnihtemos wonk ll'yeht ...yehT"
.srekcatta rehto eht fo eno morf krab a saw
nibac regnessap eht neewteb rood eht draeh nalA taht
.kcen sih dnuora morf eltsihw eht pu gnikcip dna
.mih dniheb erew syad fo sdnik eseht depoh yllaer d'eH
.demrifnoc regdab ehT ".did eruS"
.egdirb llams a ssorca detautis saw dna yllidacciP dna egdirB ediuG ekilnu
.emas eht yas ton dluoc
,sreliart bac eht fo gnikaepS
luaP saw ti taht reyarp tnelis s'nalA
saw taht krowtniap bard sti dna sthgil lanoitidda ,selbac gnikrow elpitlum sa hcus tnempiuqe no dekcat rehto eht htiw hguoht
.edisni kcab gnibmilc dna eltsihw eht gnivig neht ,draoba gnitteg ydobon