.tnemeticxe eudnu rof esuac tneitap a gnivig tuohtiw ssenlausac dexaler fo esnes a dereffo dna triks reh yb derevoc seenk reh tfel taht rennam lanoisseforp taht ni dedlof erew sgel reH
,maerts eht drawot ffo detrad eh sa
,enihw tfos a htiw dias lerriuqs eht
,hsif yrevlis ,deruolocitlum fo loohcs a won saw – gnoras sih
revolc tneluccus dna noilednad tnargarf ,wol dna
god yffulf a ,opmeT dna
klis looc fo leef eht gniyojne
pu seenk sih llup ot dellepmoc tlef eh won tub
.sredluohs s’yadiloH detanimulli nus eht dna edis eht ot deyaws
,elprup erew seye s’esuom eht taht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,sesroh dna reed fo sdreh
.eno tpecxe ,meht fo enoN
,traeh a htiw nam a osla saw eh taht won
noegnud eht ,kcilliK ,nooM ooM elbaffeni eht ,regguR .P .B ,remrahc eniuqe eht ,foohnorI mok'aT
pirg s’lerriuqs eht dna
,mih fo tnorf ni dleh latsyrc eht ta reep ot pu tas eh sa mih rednu dekaeuqs rehtaeL
.meht esolc nac uoY
,pu dekool eh nehw neve tub
drawrof raf os drawrof denael dah lerriuqs eht
.seye ytterp ylevitisop
.ygolopa ni sreksihw sih dedlof ylkciuq neht
dna ereht llits saw ehs ees ot deveiler saw lerriuqs ehT
.pu kcab og ot nosaer on fo kniht dluoc lerriuqs eht
,esuom sih htiw lerriuqs eht dna hsif sti htiw ekal eht
taht tub ,dnab gniddew sih htiw gnitegdif morf meht peek ot
,sblubhsalf dna esualppa gnoma tcetihcra daeh fo boj eht gnitpecca
a evah ot demees ti
,esuom emosdnah ,yldneirf eht ta delims ylpmis eh oS
.renroc eht ni ti peek I yhw s’taht
,lerriuqs eht thguoht
.seye sih ni sruoloc eht ta delevram eh sa
,dednuor yltcefrep a deppuc dna kcab ralucsum s’esuom eht fo epols eht nwod dils dnah sih nehw hsaleye na tab t’ndid eH
repap gnipparw samtsirhC
.eb thgim noitautafni taht trohs woh rettam on ,nrecnoc ro
.pal depparw-wobniar sih ni dedlof sdnah sih
gnitaralihxe dna hserf os dellems ria eht erehw ,ecalp sihT
,ot dlot saw eh sa ,gniyrt
,revir sti htiw nelg eht ,sdreh rieht htiw sdleif eht
,ti revo dnah sih dehsurb ylerem eh ,did yllausu eh sa ,eit sih gninethgit fo daetsni dna
.elimE ,thgir lla s’tahT“ .delims
,egnaro erew yeht won dna
,efiw sih devol eH
,flesmih rof derolpxe tey t’ndah eh shtped dna snoissap htiw
.retfa thgir etihw fo tnilg a dna
,egamiretfa tnaidar
lerriuqs tneciter eht fo tnorf ni yltneitap ti gnigniws
,latsyrc gniyaws eht no seye sih desucofer
,spetstoof tfos htiw dehcaorppa eh sa esuom eht dias ”,yadiloH si eman yM“
– sdileye desolc fo ssenkcalb teews eht gninethgirb tuohtiw srae detfut sih demraw
.niaga pu kcab gnurps yeht ylkciuq woh ta niaga ecno desirprus
,niaga dekool eh erofeb taht deciton t’ndah eh yhw derednow eh nehw tub
.seigolopa rof ecalp a ekil mees t’ndid ,ruovalf
,neerg dna wolley neht dna
,latipsoh eht ni smra detsuahxe s’efiw sih ni dleh ybab eht nopu dezag eh sa
.noitingocer fo gnap a
nrecnoc sih tsuj ton esae ot demees dna ,lanoisseforp dna suoetruoc erew sdrow ehT
,lerriuqs eht dias ”,deen on ,hO“
.htaerb peed a koot dna
,maerts eht morf dettej taht retaw fo hsalc eht dna
,did syawla eh sa
ydob suolevram siht yhw gnirednow elihw eht lla
neeb dah maelg s’latsyrc eht naht neve rethgirb saw tlep sih fo enihs etihw ehT
.toj a ton derettam
,delkcuhc ylerem alaok ehT
,retaw mraw fo ssensselthgiew dna ytiralc lufecaep eht ylno gnivael
,gnicitne erom eb dluoc maerd ro ysatnaf on esuaceb
hguoht ,mih ot enod saw emas eht dna
ssarg llat hguorht nar eh sa dnah s’yadiloH dleh eH
dna
emit tsrif eht rof deciton lerriuqs eht dna yadiloH deksa
netfo yrev od t’ndid lerriuqs eht gnihtemos
lerriuqs eht dna ,htaeneb roolfkrow eht dna
llaw eht no gnitniap a
.did ehs nehw ti dekil sselehtreven eh suovren lerriuqs eht edam ti hguoht neve dna
.drib a fo epahs reporp eht reh hcaet ot stroffe slerriuqs eht etipsed
,rumrum wol a ni deksa eh
,notuf eht no nwod kcab yal lerriuqs ehT
,trihs deveels-trohs a ni esuom etihw A
,raf os snoisses rieht fo eno yreve gnirud
.did yllausu ti ekil
.triks a ni ylnam os kool enoyna nees reven dah eh taht
,ecaf nwo sih was eh dna
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM
.ti denethgit eh raf woh rettam on ,trams kool ot esool oot syawla dna
esuom ralucitrap siht detius lacimoc os eb ot yllausu mih ot demees taht srae gib eht dna
,swap teiuqnu sih etarecracni ot sregnif sih deknil eH
,elims sih dih ylkciuq dna sreksihw sih ta dehctarcs eH
,siht naht gniyfsitas erom dna gnixaler erom
,krow dna ytud no yawa delttihw dah lerriuqs eht htuoy a esuom eht dnel ot wobniar fo hsalps a htiw flesmih fo egami rorrim detecaf-dnasuoht a
kcitshctam a retfa ekoms ekil mih dniheb gniliart liat knip niht sih
– lausu sa – alaok eht tub ,ylitsah dias lerriuqs eht
troffe sih dna ecnegilid sih dedrawer taht
.sraey ton fi ,shtnom
mih thguat dah rehtom sih sa htuom sih gnisolc
,yadiloH deksa ”?elimE uoy llac I naC“
,tnatsni na rof ,neht dnA
.worb sih no gnimrof nageb taews fo sdaeb litnu latsyrc eht no detartnecnoc dna sreksihw sih dehctiwt
.ecaf s’lerriuqs gnikrowdrah eht no
sresuort sih fo tuo maws lerriuqs eht sa dna
skcolc ta dekool syawla eh taht dekramer dah efiw sih
,ecin rehtar saw tI
.eb dluohs dlrow eht woh saw taht dna
,saw dias eh tahw daetsni tub
kcolc eht tsap neht dna
,tnatropmi t’nsaw riA
.llih eht no eert elpam eht fo erutcip eht ta dna
edutitta citegolopa s’lerriuqs eht ot demotsucca os emoceb dah ohw tub
,llew sa delims lerriuqs eht dna delims ohw
thgir ot tfel gnitoocs
”noisseS ehT“ saw sihT
taht rof esuaceb rettam t’ndid deirram saw lerriuqs eht taht ,rettam t’ndid
esuom eht htiw efil hserf a trats ot
,sredluohs eht dnuora depoots erom laed doog a dna
neht hguone gnuoy neeb dah eh taht riapsed
”.flesym ti rof gnikool yojne ll’I“
.og tel t’ndluow lerriuqs eht dna
seldnac detnecs eht
flesmih ekam dna
.eert elpam eht rednu esuom
mih rewsna t’ndid zinuM ssiM tuB
,truoc eht ni etoyoc ruoy ,ozirraC
,eciov sih fo dnuos eht htiw desaelp saw eh dna lerriuqs eht dias
.sdneirf
regnol elttil a elims flesmih tel lerriuqs eht ,seye desolc sih fo ssenkrad til-latsyrc eht ni tub
ti erow eh esool woh rettam on ,gnitcirtsnoc oot syawla saw tI
– tsiaw sih dnuora depparw lewot hcaeb a dah esuom ehT .yltcefrep
– kcottub mrif yltcefrep
– won larutan os demees ti tub
,cisum zzaj gnillor ylhtooms htiw yaws ot nageb sehcnarb s’eert eht nehw dna
sdaptoof sih rednu dehcnurc ssarg pmad ,tfoS
,retaw raelc fo ekal a won saw maerts eht dna maerts eht ta devirra dah eh tub
,dessim d’eh dezilaer t’ndah lerriuqs eht epoh fo esnes a mih evag taht noitazilaer a emac yromem eht htiW
,elam rehtona htiw saw ti taht tcaf eht dna ,siht gnirahs eb ot ,ecin tlef tI
dna reed emos gniltrats ,laer rof yellav eht hguorht dellor neht derebmemer d’eh palcrednuht ehT
yawa ti gniparcs tsomla ,esool ti gniggut
,epahs gnol sti derimda eH
”.krow ot siht rof hguone dexaler m’I kniht t’nod I“
htiw tsiaw eninimef a gniyalpsid
lerriuqs redlo eht sa noitcennoc a peed sa demees ecnalg taht tnatsni na detsal ylno ti hguoht dna
.seye sih desolc eh sa
”?ezod I fi yako ti sI“ .ecneitap dna
,edisni hself gninedrah eht esopxe ot htaehs tfos eht kcab gninniks
nus eht fo seuh eht detcelfer tlep etihw gnilzzad tahT
,ekal eht otni dna llafretaw trohs eht revo
,dehsinav neht dna maof ro sduolc ekil seidob gniknis ,gnikaos rieht htiw decnad ylfeirb taht meht htiw gnola selbbub fo duolc a gniggard ,retaw eht otni
yrrow ro niap on si ereht evol ni er’uoy nehw dna
,lla ta taht yas ot dednetni t’ndah lerriuqs ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK
meht neewteb derettacs swobniar htiw snoitcelfer elttil dnasuoht a ni deretnilps
yknip sih gnizeeuqs dnah elttil a fo noitcennoc gniwolb-dnim taht ro
,dehgual dna rehtegot sdnah reh deppalc alaok ehT
.ssob rieht rof edisa deppets regnol on dna
.etsaw a yldrah erew yeht dna
.niaga llits ti dleh ehs erofeb
ekil yawa emac trihs s’lerriuqs eht ,taht retfA
s’esuom eht gnihcuot dapeson sih
.ekal eht fo segde eht ta sdneirf rieht nioj ot ffo deirrucs dna
.mih dniheb gnicnuob liat a fo emulp s’lerriuqs eht
,sgnileef esoht fo lla saw tI
peed gnignulp yb redrah eht lla krow s’nus eht gnikam erofeb meht yrd dluoc nus eht sa ylkciuq sa meht kaos niar eht gnittel
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.kcolc eht deciton dna
,eye evitcejbo sih ot gniziremsem yletulosba sthgilhgih ralugna dna snrettap wobniar eht
.eert elpam eht yb gnidnats saw ohw
.mih dniheb hsinav notuf eht tlef dna pu doots lerriuqs eht
,reh dniheb si liat esohw
.sseldrager gniyfsitas saw htaerb eht tub
thguoht-llew dna
,niht saw cirbaf ehT
sedis htob no etamitni erom werg
ti dleh dna ti dezeeuqs eh
.flesmih no delip yllauteprep lerriuqs eht selbuort dna ssenisub fo maerts eht ni gnola nwolb
afos rehtael eht otni kcab gnipmuls
,denrub neeb dah ti fi sa
krab s’eert elpam eht otni s’DC eht fo eno deef ot nwod gninael
,krow dna ytud ylno ton tub
emod eht woleb gnitaolf erew esuom dna
.deedni mraw yrev tlef notuf eht fo rehtael eht dna
,niaga esuom eht ees reven d’eh
,esuom dekan eht dleheb eh sa rednow fo psag ylbbub a delahxe lerriuqs ehT
,sllafretaw dna sevaw ynit eht gnipmuj nomlas regae htiw nelg wollahs a hguorht gnidniw revir elttil a
ti detcarfer srehto
,sreh yas reh draeh dna
,etihw lla ,esuom a saw eH
,noitcelloc cisum ruoy peek ot ecalp revelc a tahW
.ot drawrof dekool sah eh rennid a ta dlihc a sa lufepoh sa ,deksa eh ”?ew yaM“
tlef taht tub ,hA
htiw ecaf emosdnah a
,ylbidua gnitaeb sgniw lacitsatnaf rieht
.riapsed htiw mih dellif evah thgim thguoht tahT
,seye s’esuom eht ekil ,der dna elprup ot egnahc dluow ti fi derednow eh ylfeirb dna ti dekaos niar eht sa teloiv peed ot denrut trihs krow s’lerriuqs eht fo eulb ehT
.woleb morf skcor ydnas eht ffo gnitcelfer dna evoba morf ni gniruop thgilnus
,eye s’lerriuqs eht thguac woleb raf nworb fo tnilg a
tnemtnetnoc dna ecaep fo kool a htiw erutcip eht ta dezag lerriuqs eht yaw eht
,yllaer tub won dlo oot saw eh taht dna
,nwo sih naht rehto ,tsrif eht
.der ot no gnippils erofeb eye sih thguac dah taht elprup eht ot kcab dna eulb
,esuoh eht detanimulli hsalf thgirb a dna
gniteerg a deddon eh sa noitasnes psirc eht yojne ot seot sih delggiw eh dna
,dnim s’lerriuqs eht daer dluoc eh fi sA
.won kcalb lla t’nsaw ti hguoht
flesmih ot thguoht lerriuqs eht dna
”?dlos er’yeht erehw pu kool ot em ekil uoy dluoW“
.eb dluohs ti sa saw gnihtyrevE
– triks s’esuom eht dnuof eh
,niahc sti no elgnaj latsyrc eht gnikam
,yffuts saw eciffo eht ni ria ehT
nosmirC ,nogard delcatcepseb eht ,mrywkooB irikeneN ,god retsam
– delims alaok ehT .rellams neve
dna mrif sih fo rentrap roines eht htiw sdnah gnikahs ro
,noihsaf lauxes a ni deldnah reve d’eh taht
,eert elpam sti htiw llih ehT
dah ti demees ti rehtar ro
.thgin gniddew rieht no efiw sih gnissik ekil saw mih gnissiK
,euh eulb yranidro yratnemom a otni teloiv ot neerg morf dessap seye s’esuom eht sa
,wap sih otni dellips htaehs mraw A
gniporg dna gnidnirg dna gnissik eht sa dnA
erew yas ot flesmih detcepxe eh sdrow ehT
swap rieht deknil taht pirg eht yb drawrof flesmih deggut esuom eht
.esuom eht dniheb tsuj ees dluoc lerriuqs eht taht
,rood eht yb lerriuqs eht ediseb gnidnats ,zinuM ssiM dias
,ylrettu ,gniliaf tub
yltnatsni gnipparw sgel dna smra
.devol eh esoht htiw derahs ron
,hguone tuo dehcterts eh fi sdaptoof sih htiw yretslohpu rehtael eht hcuot tsuj dluoc eh hguoht
.regnuoy edaced a mees mih edam taht
– yrrow dna kow morf seye sih dnuora smir krad
,gnikniht tuohtiw mraerof s’yadiloH no dnah sih dial eH
,ylesolc erom ti ees ot drawrof gninael flesmih dnuof lerriuqs eht dna
,htims niatnuom eht ,irauR
eciffo ’zinuM ssiM ni ti nees d’eh taht naht rehto ,ti tuoba railimaf gnihton saw erehT
niaga ecno edahs looc eht yojne esuom eht gnittel ,niaga kcab devom
.tnereffid on saw
,ssel on regnarts a
,smaerd yllis gnimaerd dna notuf eht no gniyl ,lerriuqs ehT
,moc tod rettiwT morf ,triD
tsehc sih no talf sdnah sih gniyal
doots lerriuqs ehT
,ti nettogrof evah yam eh dnA
,os od ot thgir tlef ti erehw gnikcil dna gnilzzun
– evol dna noitagilbo htiw gnilriws efil a ni noitcennoc lufrewop tub sselgninaem ,yarts fo tnemom a fo gnileef suolevram tahT
yadiloH ekil – !ti wonk did eH
ti htiw dah eh lleps feirb eht ni derimda os d’eh latsyrc eht fo selkraps wobniar eht sa lufruoloc dna eligarf sa
rebmuls rieht morf nekowa dah yeht retaw ni desremmi erew yeht taht won dna neeb syawla
,hgis detcejed a htiw dias lerriuqs eht
.gniod saw eh tahw lerriuqs eht naht retteb hcum wonk ot demees yadiloH
,rehtnap emit-lluf a ,ybigreK
,elcsum eht gnorts woh
erusaelp lautum fo tca na ni degagne shtuom
tsrif ta mih gniciton neve toN .mih
rof erac dluoc eh ylimaf a htiw nam a saw eH
,yks eulb eht ta pu kool ot niaga kcab sih otno dellor
,esolc pu ,tniap laer t’nsi ti llet ylisae nac uoy
enog gnol dna gniteelf saw tnemom eht taht ,rettam t’ndid
sti ta kool retteb a teg ot edis sih otno gnillor
.niar remmus hserf fo rettap eht yb
,zinuM ssiM dneffo ot ton sa os deppots evah ylkciuq thgim eh nepo seye sih dah d’eh fi dna
revo pirt t’ndluow ,trad-dim ni ,lerriuqs eht taht os sksed owt neewteb gnidnats ,edisa deppets eH .smra sih fo etihw eht ot ruoloc rieht tnael taht repap eulb fo sllor htiw hgih delip smra sih
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .tah yobwoc a ni
,reh dniheb gnitniap eht ta
– srorrim ni kool syawla niav eht ekil
ecafrus s’retaw eht no niar fo murd eht dna
ydob elam eht fo noitarbelec a ni rehtegot debbur seidob
,esuom eht ta kool dna nrut mih edam gnihtemos tub ,lausu sa no dereggats lerriuqs eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
ecalp fo tuo yllohw demees taht
.ti brosba dluoc eh fi sa sih tsniaga ydob lufituaeb taht dellup dna
”,emit revo enog evah ot mees I ,yrros m’I ,hO“
,latsyrc eht no detartnecnoc eh sa
,nepo seye htiw dessik yehT
.s’DC rof sesaclewej emos werdhtiw dna selohtonk eht fo eno otni dehcaer ehS
od ot evah uoy gnihtyna t’nsi ereht
,nihc s’esuom eht dehcuot dapeson sih taht
nihc sih ot tsomla
,dnah eht yb yadiloH gnidloh llitS
llew sa latipsoh eht ni ybab dnoces eht dna
,yadiloH dellac esuom eht htiw ssarg eht no nwod tas dna trofmoc rof srae sih fo spit eht dna sreksihw gnol sih kcab dehtooms eH
,gnirewoprevo dna edurc
enaJ ta delims dna daeh sih denrut eh neht dna kcab delims ohw
.llew sa selkna sih gniknil
.sraey gniniamer sih llif ot tseretni fo ytnelp saw ereht taht
.mih ot railimaf os saw
,yltcerid thgil eht detcelfer stecaf emoS .selgna psirc eht
,regnuoy sraey wef a – flesmih was eH
detnarg rof ti koot yeht taht
.resolc elttil a tas ehs dna
neerg a no wodahs sti gnitsac eert elpam a fo
.ti ni gnimmiws hsif eht ro
,dleif eht morf pu ylf ot seilfrettub desuac yeht revoc-eert fo ytefas eht rof dettort sdreh eht sa
hguone lerriuqs eht deticxe noitasnes eht dna efiw sih htiw ylno derahs d’eh won ot pu taht mih fo trap a dednuorrus spil mraW
.emit siht mih koot ti troffe hcum woh ta desirprus saw eh hguoht
.ti dias dah eh taht won aedi doog yrev a ekil dednuos ti tub
”.tuoba deklat ew ekil ,enaJ em llac dnA .devom ti woh
eciffo ’zinuM ssiM ni deyalp zzaj tfoS
denialpxe ehs ”,xaler dna kool tpecxe
,retfa yletaidemmi ti tuoba togrof dna
rehtael ,seldnac detnecs ylthgil fo dellems taht htaerb peed a koot dna
.gniliec ssalg a no fi sa
tol a taht did ehs
,deerga lerriuqs eht ”,seY“
lerriuqs eht derepsihw ”,enaJ ,yrroS“
– elbatrofmoc yltcefrep tlef eh
,thgil detcarfer eht fo ytuaeb eht yb yawa tpews eb flesmih tel ot
raelc ,nossel loohcs devoleb a ekil saw eciov sih dna
’uoy knaht ,esuoh ym ro eciffo ym ni gnitniap a fo deen on ev’I‘
swov sih dias eh nehw dnah s’efiw sih gnidloh ekil saw ti dna
yehT .daehrevo gniylf sdrib fo thgis eht ta
.stnemhsilpmocca llams on erew esoht dna
.ot mih ecudortni ot detnaw zinuM ssiM tseug eht ot
.netfo os elpoep ta delims enaJ yhw dootsrednu eh thguoht eh
niar eht fo dnuos eht yb dedualppa
eludehcs sih no txen saw taht hcnul ssenisub eht ta ssenetal sih taht tub
,repap eruza no senil licnep gnivom-wols naht erom on eb ot sa hgih os erew
.eciton ot enon dna ees ot lla rof
,ekil dekool latsyrc eht tahw rebmemer tsuJ
,ysword tlef regnol on ohw
mih rof dekrow ohw elpoep
– saw lerriuqs eht sa deticxe sa eb ot demees yadiloH
– noitcejbo on decnanetnuoc dna mih dleh dna mih ot gnulc yeht
”?edahs eht ni em nioj ot ekil uoy dluoW .yadot mraw s’tI“
ti debbur dna kcab mra sih dekrej lerriuqs ehT
reward reh ni kcab latsyrc-muludnep eht gnittup saw ohw
,dias dah zinuM ssiM sA
,rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR
,etaciled ,spih enilucsam
sdnilb s’eciffo eht hguorht deppils taht thgilnus eht taht hcus denrut saw daeh siH .doog
,tfird dnim sih tel lerriuqs eht
,daehrevo raf gnirettap niar htiw ylsselthgiew gnilbmut
,ti nruter ot yletaidemmi thguos eh taht
,dias ehs ”,em ot aedi lufrednow a ekil sdnuos tahT“ .gnilims naht
,sredluohs daorb no smra evisserpxe
dna llew sa kcab delims ehs dna
.notuf eht no thgirpu tas
pu tas lerriuqs eht nehW
,sreksihw eht ta gniyarg
.noitautafni citegolopanu dna lanoitarri fo ,spahrep ,tnemom a
.lerriuqs eht ot derrucco neve evah erofeb reven dluow taht
.mra sih revo ekorts tfos a htiw
,taht fo enon saw ereht
.erofeb ti deredisnoc reven ylpmis d’eh tub
:ecalperif eht fo sdneirf eht yb uoy rof daer ,ikahK yb
,yadiloH dellac regnarts emos ton saw smra sih ni elam ehT
.ytniatrecnu ron riapsed on
”?ti t’nsi ,ytterp s’tI“
,spahrep ,taht riapseD
,nepo erew seye sih nehw dah eh naht ylluferac erom yromem sti deiduts lerriuqs ehT
teef sih ot mih deggard ylevitisop dna wap s’esuom eht fo dloh koot lerriuqs eht ,rehtegot swap reh deppalc ehs sa dna
sthgilhsalf gninihs ,efiw sih dna mih dnuora nerdlihc rehto owt sih htiw
,dehsinav ti fo lla
daehrevo emod ssalg eht neewteb ecaps nepo eht gnidnuorrus sroolf ruof fo seinoclab htiw muirta til-llew A
.rehto eht nioj ot thguos seidob rieht fo hcae sa
ni decneirepxe d’eh naht tser repeed a gnihcaorppa flesmih tlef eh dna
,roolfkrow eht no elpoep egdod ot
,taht ta delims eH
dnah gnorts ,mraw s’yadiloH gnidloh
,ylleb delppir ylhtooms
,taorht s’lerriuqs eht ta tonk detacilpmoc eht tuo thguos dnah eerf sih dna
did eh thguoht eh sa hcum sa efiw sih evol t’ndid lerriuqs eht
.gnileef eht ton tub
maof yria fo niatnuof nwod-edispu na
,dehsinav yromem ehT
”,enoemos teem ot uoy ekil d’I“
.tegdif t’ndid sdnah s’lerriuqs eht os neve
.ydob sih ot demraw dah rehtael eht won notuf eht fo leef eht gniyojne
.sikahk tseb sih no sniats-ssarg tuoba gniyrrow ton ecno rof
yerg gniog saw eh
,seert fo sespoc htiw neerg gnillor tub dnuora gnihton htiw ,llih yssarg a no ereh tuo ,ysaenu tlef llits lerriuqs eht hguoht nevE
,xofnogard reppad eht ,nelarD
– kcolc eht ta niaga decnalg eH
.nosrep yllis a ekil gnikwag pots ot daeh sih gnikahs
pu denethgiarts lerriuqs eht
,sdileye desolc sih fo ssenkrad eht ni
”,zinuM ssiM ,truh ot gnitrats era seye yM“
.mih htiw gnola emarf sti ni erutcip eht gnidrager
”,idralloG elimE m’I“
elam saw esuom eht tahT
,gninnur elihw dehcaer d’yeht gnahrevo ykcor eht ffo tpael esuom eht dna lerriuqs eht ,noitatiseh ro thguoht tuohtiW
,ekilydal tub gnihtyna erew mih dnuora smra s’yadiloH
.thgir lla s’tahT“
,lerriuqs eht dna zinuM ssiM dias
,alaok eht tsap dekool eH
,esuoh eht ni driht eht dna
.erofeb mih nees dah lerriuqs eht
.seye sih ni epoh htiw enaJ ta dekool dna
,selbbub fo hsur a ni
eit eht taht gnitaicerppa dna
,mih ta delims alaok ehT  .llih
.ezeerb eht ni deyaws taht eert elpam eht fo wodahs gnitfihs yltnatsnoc eht ni tlenk eh dna
.swap sih htiw ecaf sih gnirevoc dna
,eman laer s’esuom eht wonk t’ndid eh taht dna
,setunim owt lluf a yb ruoh s’noisses siht deppetsrevo gnivah rof
nwod gnihsup hteet tnorf egral
!drow eht saw taht – gnoras a gniraew won
.desucxe osla won saw
.mih eziremsem ot
,pil sih tib lerriuqs ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.xaler ot yletarepsed gniyrt
,tsertoof s’notuf eht no tser ot teef sih rof trohs oot saw lerriuqs ehT
”?elimE ,kniht uoy t’nod ,mraw oot llits s’tI“ .gnilims
.eman eht wonk t’ndid lerriuqs eht hcihw fo stnemrag ngierof ycnaf esoht fo eno ,on
.detcarfer yeht thgil eht htiw mih eziremsem ot deunitnoc seye sih dna desaelp ti sa hsif eht dna skcor eht dna retaw eht dna
.gnilims saw eh yhw rebmemer t’ndluoc eh
mih drawot esuom eht dellup d’eh tub ti dezilaer neve t’ndah lerriuqs ehT
.ekil dekool latsyrc eht tahw rebmemer dluoc eh
retteb neve spahrep saw gnihgual taht thguoht won ohw
,gnitsixe rof gnizigolopa saw eh ekil dnuos t’ndid ti esuaceb
,taborca sucric a fo nodnaba eht dna recnad a fo ecarg eht htiw detaolf yadiloH
snoitasnes fo dniwlrihw a emaceb lerriuqs eht rof hcihw
ikahK yb ”noisseS ehT“   yojne esaelP  ]...[ ​​hao dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,flac gnorts ,hgiht mrif fo leef eht morf ylhtooms dewolf snoitca siH
,thgirpu tas lerriuqs trela eht yletaidemmi dna
”,gnikrow ton s’tI“
.eit sih htiw tegdif mih ekam ot devres ylno
,elims a dna don a htiW
– kcab sraey wef a pohs tfig muesum
a morf tog I tnirp ffokconk paehc a tsuj ,laiceps gnihton s’ti diarfa m’I“
.ecaf sih revo sruoloc tnaillirb sti gninnips dna
.ecaf eht ecalp ot
,tius ssenisub kcalb trams reh ni elbatrofmoc yrev os gnikool ,alaok eht dias ”,daeha oG“
,lerriuqs eht dna esuom eht did os dna
daetsni dna tsipareht sih ta kool ot ton deirt eh seye sih derevocnu eh nehw dna lla
,wonk uoy ,tset a t’nsi sihT“
.efil wen a fo thgis eht ta depsag enoyreve
derebmemer eh tub
a ot gniklat ,yawa rehtraf elttil a tsuj saw zinuM ssiM .thgir lla saw ti tuB .eciov sih ni yrrow ,deksa eh ”?zinuM ssiM“ .nrecnoc ni tuoba gnikool
.eit sih morf edisa
,mih ta dekool ehS ”.ti ekil I tuB
sehcnarb eht nehW  .noitseuq s’esuom eht ot yldi gniddon
,eugnot ,spil ,sdnaH
.mih dnuora selcric maws dna dnah sih dleh llits ohw ,ssel on ,elam a
tem spil rieht dna
yddad rof slewot gnidloh dna ssenkrad tuo-dekcalb eht tsniaga
sreksihw eht dnuora yarg ssel ylthgils
ecnatsid eht ni gnicnad hsif fo sloohcs
,dereffo esuom eht
”?maerts eht ni miws a rof tnew ew fi thgir lla eb dluow ti kniht uoy oD“
”.tneps llew emit saw ti kniht I
,ycamitni derahs ylsuoiciled fo ecnad siht ni nups seidob owt eht sa dna
,saw tlep eht tfos woh gniretsiger neve tuohtiw
evol ni saw eh tnemom eno
mottob eht ta skcor eht fo weiv eht htiw deyot selppir-niar erehw
.eciffo sih ni roolfkrow eht evoba hgih gnitaolf saw lerriuqs eht neht dnA
.desinagro-llew erew ohw elpoep dekil ohw
,zinuM ssiM ta dekool lerriuqs ehT  .gniyfsitas dna tuo-
edistuo deraor palcrednuht a nehw dna
ward ot deunitnoc tsegnuoy sih ekil
tem seye rieht tnatsni eht tsuj rof esuom emosdnah eht htiw evol ni neeb d’eh spahreP .taht ta delims
gnirrulb erew ti hguoht sa edaf latsyrc eht fo egami eht gnittel
,gnicneirepxe erew emod ssalg eht rednu gnitaolf esuom wobniar eht dna
,eert eht rednu elpoep eht naht erom maerts eht ni hsif eht rof gnos a gniyalp eb ot demees taht enohpoxas a fo snoitanotni yzal eht yb pu tpews ,sehcnarb ehT
.tniap tew fo egdums kciht a erew ti fi sa
dehcaerrevo ylkciuq hguoht
.elbatrofmoc yltcefrep saw
ta eruliaf ekil t’ndid eH
,mih deripsni taht krow dna
.taht rof ezigolopa ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc lerriuqs eht
,latsyrc-muludnep eht dloh ot deunitnoc ehS
,srae sih dedlof dna dias eh ”,yrros m’I“