.syaw gnignahc eht ot ssecca dah evah reven thgim ehs
.epacse ot drah os deirt dah ehs elor eht otni kcab decrof gnieb
.esrow htiw denetaerht ,dehsinup
ytleurc enifer ot woh mih nwohs dah ohw
doolb reh dna eye reh evag ohw
pu doots yob eht ,tsal gnol tA
.gniusrup era ew laog hcihw
,niaga esira mih ekil slaudividni live nehw ,taht os ,reh rebmemeR
.yllaretil semitemos
.ytilibicnivni sih tuoba seil nwo sih ni eveileb ot nugeb oga gnol dah eh esuaceb
,detserra saw ehS
.esneterp lla denodnaba eh
.erac ton did ylpmis dna ti dezilaer ohw esoht ,lla fo tsrow ,ro
,htaerb peed a koot dna
.detavitluc ylluferac
.secnatsmucric thgir eht htiw dna
.egar sih ecaf ot evah ton dluow yeht taht os
.siht detsegid dna kcab tas yob ehT
.llew sa seilla dah nam eht tub
,elttab laturb a saw tI
.ytleurc tuoba gniht suoiruc a si ereht tuB
.syaw eht klaw ot hguone yhtrow saw ohw fo
erew yeht ohw sa efil tsenoh na dehsiw ylpmis ohw esoht dekcatta eH
sevlesmeht rof ediced ot thgir eht evah thgim enoyreve taht
,sehceerb rof sesserd dehs ot ylno dehsiw ohw
sa efas sa ,efil reh tuo devil evah dluoc ehs taht
,retal elttil a nrob neeb ehs daH
.drawrof pets ton did eH
,hsiw uoy sa gnol sa rof edis ruoy yb eb lliw I ,dlihc yM“
evael tsuj dluoc ehs
.ytleurc dna dertah fo ycagel a no eripme na tliub eh tub
.derrab yaw reh dnuof tub
,tib elttil a detegdif yob ehT ”.hO“
.kaeps ot ytiliba reh yortsed ot deirt ,deliaf taht nehw dna
”yhW nosaeR ehT“ saw sihT
,od ot dah dah ehs naht erom on od ot evah dluow srehto
rewop ot htap a egrof ot dna
suoirolg a si ti
?eb ot deen ton seod ti esuaceb evarb ton si sevlesruo sa gnivil dna
,elitsoh eb ot raeppa ton did tI
.legna gnigneva na fo yruf eht lla htiw tuo dehsalf drows reH
,ecitsuj fo selacs eht erob hcihw
.snoitca reh yb nwonk eb ot dehsiw ehs esuaceb eman reh uoy llet ton did I“
meht ot neppah dluow tahw deraef stnenoppo sih erehw
.elbarenluv eht fo doolb eht fo tuo
.daeh taerg sti denilcni nogard ehT
,daed eht fo srebmun eurt eht wonk reven yam eW
.mih ot leurc sa eb tsuj dluoc ti taht dnuof dna
dlrow elbissop tseb eht eb ot ti deveileb dna
.romra reh fo egde eht rednu
,raw larutluc regral a fo
tfarg yb denekaew tnemnrevog a saw ti tub
,dluoc ehs enoyreve htiw ekops ehS
,srehto tneverp ot thguof ehS
.flaheb sih no thgif ot ymra sih ecrof ot ytiliba on dah
etanutrofnu sa ffo ti etorw srehto dna
,reh erongi regnol on dluoc eh nehW
.serised nwo rieht tius ot
.edih ton did ehS
,gniht gniyfirret a si tI .tliub dah
namow eht rebmemer uoy taht si
,noitpecni sti morf raw eht nees dah ohw ,namow ehT
.elbicnivni ton si
,trapa llaf dluow ymra sih neht ,now ehs fI
.niaga doolb gniward ,romra sih fo spag eht neewteb deppils rehtona dna
,reh fo edam gnitniap yreve dna
.tserof eht fo moolg gnitrofmoc eht ni
.mih revo gnirewot erutaerc taerg eht ta pu denworf
meht ot ksir eht nehw
.noitcetorp reh rof erew tuo tes yeht selur eht taht
.ytilibarenluvni sih fo llet ot yrots a
.ecaep ni efil reh fo tser eht tuo evil ot deriter ehs
.are suoiverp eht fo sessecxe eht tsniaga tcetorp ot dengised
,tneler ton dluoc eH
redisnoc ot egnarts si tI
,dne eht nI .eno trohs a tub
”.era ew ohw ediced ew ,dne eht ni tub
.mih dna flesreh neewteb
,nerdlihc tneverp ot
,tsixe ton seod yrtogib erehw sdlrow ot gniripsa ew erA
,tnemunom eno ylno dengised ehS
,dias neht ,detatiseh yob ehT
,ysae spahrep si tI
.ti ediba ton dluoc
.syaw gnignahc eht ot ecnartne eht tuo kees ohw srehto lla dna ,esoohc ot
,ti ecneirepxe ot dah reven erofereht dna
drows reh desiar namow eht
,dlrow tcefrep a tuoba
,denosaer yeht ,lla retfA
.gniniamer noitpo ylno
flesreh evres ot thgif ton did ehS
.dias ehs tahw ot netsil dna pots ot dah ti litnu
did namow eht tahw enod evah dluoc nosrep eno yna taht eetnaraug a ton si ti
,ereht mih pots ot hguone neeb evah dluohs tahT  .uoy ekil
,namow eht ot yltaerg delaeppa osla tI
,naeco eht sa elbaturcsni dna eneres ,nogard ehT
.ot nur ot secalp efas wef erew ereht ,emit taht ni
thgin eht ni delf sreciffo sih fo tsal eht taht
.ti rof esu on dah ohw slaudividni yb dedraug ylsuolaej erew syaw eht ot secnartne ehT
.retteb leef mih edam taht erus yleritne ton saw eH
,rewop ot nam siht del dah taht shtap eht dezingocer dah erom fi spahreP
,decaf ehs seitluciffid eht dah dah reven thgim ehs
,edis reh yb thguof sdneirf dna
,dehgual nogard ehT
worg ot eunitnoc tsum dna
,enod saw eh nehW
,yenom dah eH .noitpurroc dna
,esruoc fo ,deronoh saw ehS
,syaw gnignahc eht deklaw dah ehS
neppah dluow tahw denraw dna
,dias ehs ,rednimer A
.elpoep tsom fo ecnetsixe yad-ot-yad eht no tceffe elttil dah
,rewop fo tifeneb eht dah yehT
.reduol ekops ehs oS
reh taht eveileb ot sa sselfles os tub
,derettahs dna nwod dellup erew seigiffe siH
.syaw gnignahc eht lortnoc ot thguos ohw srepeeketag eht tsniaga kcab dehsup elpoeP
,namow eht rof sA
thgif ot yap ot hgih oot ecirp on si ereht taht
,revewoh ,eman sih uoy llet ton did I“  .ytinav eb thgim
.noitan reh dedavrep taht dertah eht ot nekowa dah ohw srehto derehtag dna steerts eht ot koot ehS
,rewop niag ot elpoep fo sepyt eseht fo tsrif eht ton saw eH
,era yeht hguoht wef ,seutats reH
,thgif eht niw ot hguone peed ton
.lortnoc fo ,yenom fo
,mih htiw tas nogard ehT
niap no tliub emiger a troppus ot thguof yeht taht ezilaer ton did ohw esoht fo edam eno
reh dlot sreep reh fo ynam ,deednI
,thgif lanosrep a esohc ehs dna
,ecnetsixe ni yoj tsenoh
.ecalp sih ni eid ot eno on htiw tfel saw eh dna
,esruoc fo hguoht
,namow lufituaeb a saw ehs taht uoy llet nac I
noitrop llams a saw ssecca revo thgif sihT .yltsenoh dna
,reh fo eciton koot eh
,syaw eht gnillortnoc yb taht was yeht ,tey esrow ,rO
yaw eht devap dah ohw esoht
,thgif eurt a ni ecneirepxe on dah nam ehT
,dedeen yeht tahw tuoba srehto detacude yehT
,tcilfnoc lanif eht rof ydaer
,tserof repeed eht
”.ydaer era uoy fi ediced uoy elihw yrots a uoy llet nac I ,hsiw uoy fI“
ytlausac etanutrofnu ,ronim a sa
,snoitibma sih rof
diaper eb reven nac taht ydegart a si efil eno neve fo ssol eht :siht rebmemer
,dnahffo sih ot drows sih hctiws ot decrof saw eH
.od dluohs ehs tahw saw taht
,ymene na dednarb saw namow ehT .enola mih dna
troppus gniworg saw erehT
eht semoceb thgif eht erofeb rehto hcae rof thgif ot si ti yrassecen woh
gnieye ,detatiseh yob ehT
,yrotsih ni semit rehto nI
.ytic eht detarebil ymra reh
,trofmocsid emos leef thgim uoy dna egnahc wols a si tI .tib a toN“
yltnatalb os motsuc dna mron yreve gnitaloiv
.ecnedifnoc sih nekahs dah wolb eht spahreP
.etaf ylpmis saw ti spahrep rO
.nwod kcab ton dluoc
.romra sih edisni elibommi mra thgir sih gniredner ,ecarberer dna
”,em ekatsim ton oD“
.rotatceps esirnus eht ,ogniD mailliW yb uoy rof daer ,enrohtwaH .S.J yb
,semirc tserid eht fo reh desucca
,rewop sih tnemec ot desu eh
secifircas reh gnitneserper
,efil ni sgniht ynam htiw sA
,elpoep sa ton ,detaert erew smitciv ehT
,modgnik eht fo trap etomer emos ni deniatnoc ylefas saw namow eht taht
flesti ydemer dluow taht melborp yraropmet A
,ymene na reh dednarb eH
,kcen sih gnola hctarcs a
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb ygolohtna rorroh a
,tuo reh tuhs ot detpmetta tnemnrevog nehW
,efas yletelpmoc saw eh taht mih dlot dah srosivda tsal siH
.elgnarts ot deirt dah eh ytic eht fo steerts eht ni
,pets hcae htiw dnA
deliar ehs os dnA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.drows a fo pit eht no decnalab
:taerht a erew srehto ecnivnoc ot drah os dekrow dah eh sgniht eht fo noitcurtsed eht dna
”?elihw a em htiw klaw dluoc uoy kniht uoy od …tuB“
esoohc ot modeerf eht
,now eb ot ezirp a detneserper doolb reh ,mih roF
,sdrow sih revetahW
trohs riah sih tuc ot
.rewop ni regnol on saw eh nehw
,srehto yb decneulfni eb yam lla eW
.sah ti tahw ot flesti tnetnoc ton seod
.elbatrofmoc flesmih edam eh sa sserd sih gnignarra
uoy rof modeerf eht
,htap eht ot txen nwod flesti dial nogard ehT
,nam eht ot htrib nevig dah yeht sa ylerus sa ti ot htrib evag taht stoor detsiwt eht morf
regna sih saw taerg os taht dias si tI
,enrohtwaH .S.J yb ”yhW nosaeR ehT“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.sniamer noitpircsed ron egami on
,deveileb evah neve yam
ekats ta si tahw wonk lliw uoy taht ,lliw yeht dna
.yltfos derednow yob eht ”,taht lla did ehS“
.dluohs ti reh dlot niarb reh sa noitcnuf ton did taht ydob a ni pu gniworg
.deksa nogard eht
,noisacco no ,ekops ehS
.gnorts dna peed nar stoor s’nam siht dnA
emaceb detpurroc ehT
,eb ot erehw meht dewohs ehS
,daets sih ni elttab od ot srehto tnes nam ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,evah ew sa raf sa neve teg ot selggurts eht
,syaw gnignahc eht klaw ot detnaw ehs ,namow sihT
.detpurroc eht emaceb elbitpurroc ehT
lenitnes ylacs ,krad a
,pmuts eht no ylluferac tas neht
”.kcab nrut ot ediced tonnac uoy erehw syaw eht gnola tniop on si ereht
,reh morf yawa elpoep eht nrut ot deirt eH
,thguof yeht elihW
,efil ni etanutrof saw ehS
.efil reh tub gnihton tsol dah ehs dna
.eb nac efil suotipidneres woh
.syaw gnignahc eht levart ot dehsiw ehs ,uoy ekil ,dna
rewop taht stegrof eno
,ytterp meht ekam ot dah dah ecnis emit gnol yrev a neeb dah ti
.erew yeht woh ylno
,stsigetarts delliks yub ton dluoc eh tub
,tcartnoc laicos eht fo tecaf yreve ekorb yehT
.daeh rieht ta gnithgif ,elttab otni elpoep reh del namow ehT
,syaw eht no sregnad erew ereht reh dlot yehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,reh rof thguof weF
.ytefas fo tsoc eht saw
,tnemnrevog fo sisab yreve gniluofeb fo sraey retfa
,mih ot yltaerg delaeppa taht noitisoporp a saw tI
.sgniht hcus dewehcse ehs ylegral tub
.esle erehwemos og dna
.sedit eht denrut evah dluoc ecnahc fo tib a nehw semit ynam erew erehT
.raw yrassecen dna tsuj a neve
derettilf noisserppo fo secrof eht
.drows a gnisiar tuohtiw thgif ot woh
.eb nac nam eno taerht eht dootsrednu dah erom fi
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.raeh ot detnaw ti tahw ti llet ot ,thguoht eh
.hceeps sih ot ytilibatcepser fo reenev tsenniht eht ylno saw ereht dna
racs reh taht detsisni ehs
.noitartnecnoc ni deworruf worb sih
.eciohc ruoy si ti taht dnatsrednu uoy taht os
dedihc saw ehs ,yaw rehtona
,gnihtyreve yortsed ot gnilliw era yeht taht
,egami sih ni dlrow a
,ybraen gnilttes ylerem tub ti gnikcolb ton
.denitsederp saw raw siht fo emoctuo eht taht yas ot ton si hcihW
,sreh dna ,doolb sih ,hguoht ,reh roF
naht erom ,erised taht ekil elpoep esuaceb
,dnah rehto eht no ,now eh fI
.seye eulb ecsenimul dna
,dekover gnieb ssecca reh ni tluser dluow
.llaf rieht dna semirc rieht ylno rebmemer dna
,ronoh reh ni desiar eb ot dettimrep ehs seutats wef eht nI
,thgis no dellik eb ot
,rennab reh hctam ot drows a pu koot ehS
,lufrewop erom emaceb eh sa ,nam siht oS
,flesreh rof thguof ehs os
,ylidaets ,ti detsiwt dna
eh–eman eurt reh yb ot refer neve ton dluoc eh namow
,yob eht ta nwod gnirats ,tas nogard ehT
,sworg dna semusnoc ti
.tnemnrevog wen eht ni noitisop yna tpecca ot desufer ehs
.reh ot desolc tnemnrevog fo sllah eht dnuof ehs ,tnew ehs erehW
* * * .detnaw reve dah ehs lla
.tsal reh ton saw tih tsrif reh
.yllanosrep meht tceffa ton seod ti nehw niap erongi ot deniart osla era yeht
elpoep ni taerht a was ohw esoht etalupinam dluoc yeht
,derujni eb dluoc eh taht ezilaer ot mih decrof dah hctarcs taht spahreP
.elbissop sa ylhsrah sa htiw tlaed eb ot srewollof dna sretroppus reh
,deid dna ton did ynaM .did ynaM
”?dlihc ym ,syaw gnignahc eht levart ot kees uoY“
.reh tcetorp ot erew selur eht taht dias yehT
.emocrevo ydaerla dah ehs esohT
,detlit dlrow eht nehw oS
.erised uoy sa snoitseuq ynam sa ksa yam uoy ,dlihc yM“
,srehto evas dna tcetorp ot
raw morf yawa denrut dah ohw ,nam ehT
,etah fo nrob rewop ylralucitrap ,rewoP
,elttab lanif rieht rof selur eht tes namow eht ,dne eht nI
,tih tsrif eht derocs eH
”?syaw gnignahc eht klaw ot gnitnaw tuobA“
.tas eh hcihw no niap deredro
,decaf evah ew spihsdrah eht gnigdelwonkca ew era rO
.kcatta eht desserp ehs dna
.eh naht retaerg emaceb
.gnihton enod evah dluoc namow ehT
.flesruoy tuoba elbaulav gnihtemos denrael evah lliw uoy nehT“
uoy fo ksa I taht lla neht
,yllatnedicca syaw eht deklaw eno on erus eb ot detnaw yeht dias yehT
.tsoc eht rettam on rewop ezies ot thguof elpoep yrgna dna suolaej erehw
,hguoht ,hturt eht erew taht fi nevE
tis naht erom od ot hguone egral ymra na esiar ot elbanu
,ydaerla ton dah yeht hguoht sa
.luos rieht laeh tseb lliw tahw
.msitopsed sih rednu evil ot decrof slaudividni eht rof elbirroh erom emaceb
”.deined saw ehs ytefas eht evah dluow uoy taht reh ot erom derettam tI“
.mih ot noitacided yb ylelos rehtegot dleh
,erif a ekil si tI
os dah eh taht ytleurc dna esuba fo elcyc elbatrofmoc eht ot trever dluow dlrow sih dna niw dluow
.nosaer a rof detsixe yeht taht
,elur ot dertah timrep
.nosaert dna noitides htiw reh degrahc
,renetsil ,uoy rof noitseuq eht rewsna ot emuserp ton ll’eW
,nward sdrows rieht ,tem yehT
.syaw eht deklaw reven dah ehs hguoht sa gnissap fo elbapac ylluf saw ehs
.sregnad esoht morf reh tcetorp ot gnihton did selur eht taht
,selur eht dewollof ehs tuB
,hguoht ,reh erofeb kaerb ton did eH
.ssentiw ro rethgif rehtehw
,ynam ot ,demees tI
,lla retfa ,saw tahT
.edis reh ta thguof ohw esoht no niap erom ecrof ot erised on dah
,taht deneppah ti oS
.yub dluoc yenom taht srotut tseb eht dah dah eh tub
.reh retfa emoc dluow ohw esoht rof dlrow retteb a dliub ot
enrohtwaH .S.J yb ”yhW nosaeR ehT“
,tsal eht eb eh lliw ron
,noitanmad ot flesti yromem rieht nmednoc ew taht
,ecnesba reh ni no eunitnoc dluow ymra reh neht
,snoitnetni doog dah meht fo emoS
.tserof eht otni htap krad eht gnicaf
srehto lortnoc t’ndluoc eh yhw dnatsrednu ton dluoc tub ,lortnoc dah eH
yob a rof sthguoht ydaeh erew esehT
srehto ot nialpxe ot elba erew ohw dna
.reh ekil srehto rof dna
,ecaep thguos ohw esoht gniwoc ,meht detcefni
,leets fo rallip a ,si dna ,saw tI
,nam eliv siht dnA
”?nur ehs t’ndid yhW“  ”.eid ro
,lla retfa ,dah eH
,daeherugif rieht tuohtiW
.yaw s’mrah ni ylerauqs os ton erew ohw srehto nraw ot elat yranoituac a ,yrogella sa tub
.mih ta delims nogard eht dna
.daeh taerg sti koohs nogard ehT  .deksa eh
.syaw eht yduts dna tcetorp ot erised tsenoh na
reffo daetsni tub
,elbarenluv tsom eht gnitruh no desimerp dlrow a sdliub eno nehw
,emoc dah namow eht litnu rof
,yltnatropmi erom ,dna
.yhtrow saw ehs taht reh pots ot rewop eht dah ohw esoht dedausrep ehS .erom dna
,detfard erew swal weN
ytleurc fo dlrow a desimorp eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.emit tsetrohs eht rof neve
.dedeen ehs tahw ot resolc eno tiebla
,gnivom ylerab ,gnikaeps ton
,mih llafeb ot mrah yna dewolla yeht fi
selacs krad fo lenitnes a
,smodgnik rehto ot tuo dekael ydaerla dah live sihT
”.og ot ediced uoy syaw eht nwod raf revewoh
.sevil rieht ot tnavelerri yletamitlu tub
msiurt das a si tI  .srelur
uoy ekam nac uoy ylnO“
,ot edam saw ehs sa
.uoy ekil elpoep roF
.netsil ot ton denraw erew rewop dah ohw esoht ,ekops ehs nehW
retibra eht gnieb ni rewop was srehtO
,htap taht klaw ot ydaer tey ton era uoy fi taht ro
.evol ,ytiuqe ,ytsenoh
.eulav on dah lortnoc fo smetsys eht woh
”?gnorw m’I fi tahW“
a–namow eno siht gnivomer yb taht thguoht eH
.gnivieced eb dluoc ,ecnetsixe trohs sih ni denrael dah yob eht ,secnaraeppa tub
,yllacitats tsixe tsuj ton seod sih ekil dertaH .no kcab kool ot
,syaw eht levart reh tel ot gnilliw saw ohw enoemos dnif ot sraey reh koot tI
”.sdrawoc yttep fo sdertah yttep eht morf eerf eno si dlrow tcefrep A“ ,ylpmis ,dias dna
,dlog dna eulb fo rennab a rednu srehto deillar ehs
,ecnatsiser yna gnicaf reve tuohtiw efil eritne na sevil eno nehW
elzzum reh no racs a tfel dna eye reh koot tsurht ykcul A
.tuo detoor sselnu
reve dluohs eno oN
ereht ,oga emit gnol yrev a ,ecnO
dednamed nosrep taht sksat eht fo lla mrofrep ot taht fo pot no raey rehtona dna
,ecalp thgir eht ni dna
,draeh eb dna lley ot woh
,tnaw uoy tahw ton si siht ediced uoy fI
egelivirp dna ssecca tneiciffus dah
,srossecederp fo enil gnol a
”?noitseuq rehtona ksa I naC“
.raw nwo sih ni tseretni yna gniwohs fo elbapacni ylpmis ro gnilliwnu
”?seman rieht em llet uoy t’ndid yhW“
,mih tsniaga drows a pu ekat ot derad evah dluow enon
.syaw gnignahc eht ot ro
.eelf ton did namow siht taht si wonk od ew tahW
,reh morf yrots reh wonk dna
ruf kcalb krad htiw ,gnorts dna llat
.ot dah ehs tahw od ot edutitrof eht dah evah t’ndluow dna
:detnaw ehs tahw si tahT
,ytleurc fo dlrow a tliub eH
.dliw dna tsol erew syaw gnignahc eht ,syad esoht nI
.sniatnuom eht ot saes eht morf
.syaw eht klaw ot dewolla yllanif saw ehs nehw tluda na saw ehS
.mih dniheb deyaws liat depirts ,gnol siH .dias eh ”,od I“
,niav ton saw ehs taht uoy llet nac I
,elbatrofmoc eht ot taerht reh fo
tnemhcirne lanosrep ot detacided os puorg a gnireffus fo sregnad eht ro
,mih dedecerp dah ohw dna mih ekil esoht dna ,nam eht tahw emocrevo ton dluoc namow eht taht deraeppa ti gninnigeb yrev eht morF
,eelf ot snaem dna troppus htob dah dna
,dnuow eht yb decnelis ,deid eh dna
,efil reh dah evah dluoc ehS .esle enoyna sa
.tpurretni ot htuom sih denepo yob eht nehw deunitnoc nogard eht
,devol ehs taht liat yhsub ,gnol a dna
,lla evoba ,dna niap dna
,derebmemer eb ot ,esle gnihtyna
,derednow yob eht ,eh dluoC
,tcetorp ot thguof ymra reh tub
”?uoy llet ot yrots taht esohc I yhw gnirednow er’uoY“
.yleerf erom evil yam srehto taht snaem ti fi
,dias eh ”,ydaer m’I“
,seoreh sih dna flesmih ot tnemunom a otni tliuber dah nam eht taht tub ecalptekram gniltsub a neeb ecno dah tahw
,trohs oot ton tub
,wal fo tnemnrevog a sih saw regnol oN
.elttab fo segde eht dnoyeb evil ot dniheb raw eht tfel ylpmis ro
,thguoht ehs revetahw
dna gnireffus was ehS
.nialliv ro oreh sa rehtehw
,fo tnemnrevog a tub
.htap reh deklaw ehs dna
,dnal siht ssorca degar raw riehT  .deidemer ro
,detcefed sreidlos detnelat tsom sih fo wef a naht eroM
retuoc eht detned ehs
,ytic latipac eht ta devirra ymra reh nehw taht dias si tI
.mih dnuora enoyreve no detcilfni eh taht ytleurc eht no
.draehnu og dluow saelp reh yltneuqerF
,ymra gnidnats a tuohtiw
,ymra na dah llits eH
.etah fo sgalf welf ohw esoht gninedlobme
,taorht sih hguorht drows reh evord ehs
,emit a rof syaw eht delevart evah uoy retfa ro won rehtie
,retteb eb dluow ti ebyaM
.mih rof eid ot gnilliw ymra na ro
.hguone saw taht taht uoy llet dluoc I ,dlihc ym ,hsiw I
,ecnerefed etulosba ot deltitne leef ohw slaudividni fo egatrohs on si erehT
.toor ekat ot ytleurc hcus dettimrep dah ohw esoht tsniaga deirc dna deliar ehs erehw
,tnagorra erom hcae
.romra eht gniluof dna htaenrednu liam eht gnireves edalb reh
.liaverp dluohs ecitsuj taht elbativeni eb ot
,gniht elbirret a si raW
.ytsenoh no devloser yob eht dna
.noitseuq emas eht sksa
.naidraug a ton ,ediug a ma I .dlihc ym ,hO“
deruces eh noitisop hcae ,teY
.esruoc fo ,ereht dne ton did raw ehT
,mih fO .dnats llits
.tcilfnoc tnatropmi erom a ni
.noisiced dilav dna enif a si taht neht
,rewop fo sllah eht ot tsrif reh thguorb thgif reH
.reh retfa emoc dluow ohw esoht fo tsoc eht ta
.daeh evissam sti koohs nogard ehT
ecifircas rebmemer ot srehto detnaw ehs dna
.deddon yob ehT
rettiwT reh tuo gnikcehc yb krow reh htiw etad ot pu peeK
,ylgninethgirf dna ylneddus
,tib tseinit eht neve
.owt eht fo resiw eht gnieb
.reverof evivrus tonnac taht ekil nem taht yas ot ,gnitpmet dna
.mih deraef regnol on ohw enoemos tsniaga htaed eht ot thgif eurt a dna
,detatiseh eh ”,ti lliW“
,yrotciv reh fo terces taerg eht saw tahT
,dlihc yM .thguof yehT
* * * ”.syaw gnignahc eht fo yrots a si tI“
,htob gnieb yb ,taht yrots a
”?truh ti lliW“ .dewollaws eH
.nialp saw tnetni sih
.tserof repeed eht ot ecnartne eht raen sehcnuah sti no tas
,tserof eht ta nogard eht tsap dekool yob ehT
.ytiuqe dna ecitsuj fo esuac eht ot srytram
.sretsam neewteb elttab eurt a ees ot gniht elbirret dna
,tserof repeed eht hguorht klaw tsum eno shtap eht ot sregnad era ereht elihw dnA
,sreh ton erew taht elor a dna
.edalb a eldnah ot woh nrael ot ecneirepxe rettib fo sraey gnol ynam dah dah ehs tub
,revewoh ,ton si ecitsuJ
yojne esaelP ,rotatcepS esirnuS eht ,ogniD mailliW yb daeR
tsetaerg eht si tI
,stegrat tsrif yrev sih gnomA
mih hguorht dna ,yb
,emit thgir eht ta nrob saw ehS
,drows eht ni gniniart lamrof dekcal namow ehT
,doog yllatnemadnuf era elpoep elihw tub
,latipac eht fo egde eht no azalp taerg a ni
.seciohc rieht detterger eno on taht
.reh rof deniltuo yaw eht morf deyarts yeht fi
,tnereffid neeb evah thgim sgniht woh wonk yllaer reven nac eW .spahreP
.mih detroppus ohw esoht esaeppa ot smitciv erom gnideen flesmih dnuof eh
,did ylerar ehs hguoht ,esohc ehs fI
.reh ekil elpoep rof ytinutroppo dna
.emag a siht kniht ton did ehs taht wohs ot hguone tub
.tneitap saw enot sti hguoht
.yrotciv ysae na saw siht taht kniht ton od tuB
,tnemnrevog a dah nam ehT
,syaw gnignahc eht fo srepeeketag eht ot nedloheb regnol on saw ehS .oN“
,oge nwo sih yb detcefni os
,ytterp ton erew sdrow siH
.deksa nogard eht
,sraey trohs wef a retfa tub
,tserof eht fo moolg eht ni tuo ekam ot drah saw tI
.yltnereffid dedne evah dluoc siht spahreP
,rewop ot yaw sih gniwalc llits saw eh elihw neve
hceeps esoidnarg a edam nam ehT
,sraey neet sih otni tey ton knuks gnuoy a ,yob ehT
,egatooF dnuoF ni yltnecer tsom dnuof eb nac ohw
.mih ta delims ti ,deddon yob eht nehW
.esirprus a t’nsaw dna saw tI  .ydaer saw ehs
”.detimilnu si emit yM
,elbirroh ylurt emaceb sgniht fi neve
.flesreh fo trap a evol ot niav saw ehs taht detsisni ehs sa neve
.spihsdrah emas esoht ecaf ot gnivah morf ,uoy ekil
,dias yeht ,siht reh dlot ohw elpoep ehT
,temleh sih detned ekirts rehtonA
,did ehs tahw si reh ot derettam tahW
,lasopsid reh ta snaem yna yb ,tlah a ot ti dnuorg ehs
.sevil ro seman s’daed eht fo yllat eurt a evah reve ew lliw ron
.lla retfa nosrep doolb dna hself a saw eh taht
,gnineppah saw ti taht eveileb dluoc wef taht
”?yrots fo tros tahW“
.rewop fo snier eht fo dloh koot laudividni emoshtaol ylralucitrap eno
,reh htiw doots dah elpoep erom fi spahreP
.das denrut elims s’nogard ehT
.sdrow fo elttab a saw ti ,gninnigeb eht nI
,dluoc yeht revetahw fo dloh debbarg yehT
.tnemom eht rof tsael ta ,deid dna
tniop prahs-eldeen a otni
.srehto fo sehsiw eht ton dna
.hguone neeb dah ti
,seciffo detrossa rieht fo sesuba tsrow eht neve rof secneuqesnoc decaf reven dah ohw hcae
,tsal eht naht elbirroh erom
.flesti evas ot ylno thguof sih elihw
?emoc ot llits esoht ecaf ot noitanimreted eht dna
,seirots eseht rehtohcae llet ew sa ,sevlesruo gniksa htrow si tI
.eciffo morf mih evomer ot redrah ti ekam ot
yleerf evil ot naht erom gnihton detnaw ohw
.gnivorpmi ,trap tsom eht rof ,neeb dah efil ,sraey roF
.gnitiaw hguoht sa
eman a dengissa neeb dah ehs ,nrob saw ehs nehW
.deraef eb ot gnihtemos ,noitaived a
,nam ehT  .doolb ni
,nosaer eht revetahW
eerf sa ,esle enoyna
,htap tnereffid a dedeen ehs taht nialpxe ot deirt ehs fI
,ekortskcab eht nO
flesmih detcelfer taht eman a esoohc ot
,uoy ekil ,knuks a saw ehS .lrig a saw
.ytic eht delf neht dna
siht ezilaer did ohw ro
,raw eht fo etats eht tuoba mih ot eil ot nageb slareneg sih taht dna
”.siht od ot dedeen yllaer I taht uoy ecnivnoc ot evah dluow I dias yeht …I“
,hgiht reh tsniaga eno peed a
,lavaehpu taerg fo emit a saw tahT
.regnol hcum tsal ton did raw eht tuB
:thguof ehs yhw nosaer eht fo esuaceb now ehS .dne eht ni
,noisserppo morf gnieelf fo daetsnI
,mih dlot nogard eht ”,dlihc ym ,dias I“
,ecalp siht fo yrotsih eht wonk ot tnatropmi si ti esuaceB“
,emosraef saw htarw sih taht dias si tI
,gnithgif eht ot dne na naht
,eb ot dettimrep gnieb ylpmis ni
.reh truh ot gnitiaw sgniht
,tih txen eht dednal ehS
.3nrohtwaHSJ@
,reh ekil elpoep erew
.slaog esoht eveihca ot snaem reluof dna rekrad ot detroser
,detsetnocnu elur ot ,rewop thguos ohw esohT .elbativeni
,emit revo ,dnuof ehs
reh ees thgim srehto taht os delevart dna
.tneserp yllacisyhp eb ot gnivah tuohtiw dedeen ehs tahw meht morf ekat ot elba
,thgir eht no nordluap sih fo stnemges eht neewteb mih thguac ehS
,snoitibihxe degats neewteb ecnereffid eht ezingocer ot edam saw yllanif eh spahreP
”.thgir si tahw od dna
,nwod meht ekorb ehs
,ti hguorht evil ohw esoht stnuah tI
,drib suoiruc a sa hcum os gnihton fo mih gnidnimer
,pmuts taht naht rehtruf on og uoy fI
.demlehwrevo os eb ot
.decneirepxe dah yeht srorroh eht yb dehcuotnu ymra s’namow eht saw roN
.tserof repeed eht retne ot enoyna timrep dluow yeht erofeb
.desirprus yletelpmoc saw eh
,reh tsniaga derrab erew srood nehW .redrah eht lla
,rewop ni sniamer taht ekil nam a regnol eht dnA .dne eht ni
.nam eht htiw thgif reh ni dellips tsrif doolb reh nehw won sdnats hcihw
”.truh ton lliw ti tub
.noitcetorp tsael eht htiw esoht tegrat dna taogepacs lliw slaudividni fo live tsom eht taht
,eciov tneitap ,eltneg sti ni nogard eht dias ”,dlihc yM“  ”?eb ot tnaw I ohw em ekam ti lliW“ ,no degnulp neht
reh ot noitagilbo yna evah uoy taht ylpmi ot siht uoy llet t’ndid I“
.tnaw yeht tahw teg ot ,flesti dnal eht gnidulcni
.efil reh fo tser eht rof erow ehs taht
,revewoh ,uoy ot elbaliava noitpo taht ekam ot tsoc ti tahw wonk dluohs uoY“
.sredluohs dna smra reh dedoolb sekortsretnuoc sih dna
”?ot evah t’ndid ehs tuB“
.eb ot tnaw uoy ohw
,rewop fo srevel eht revo sthgif ,selttab gib esehT
.yawa raf ton pmuts nrow-llew a detacidni dna
”.flesruoy si ecnivnoc ot deen uoy nosrep ylno ehT
?etag eht fo repeek siht tsurt
:suoregnad eb ot saw tnereffid eb ot taht sevlesmeht decnivnoc srehto tey dnA
.hgual a fo revir delppad-nus ,hcir a
,rehtona rof ydob elbatrofmocnu eno edart ot decrof saw ehS
.lirep nwo rieht ta snoitca rieht fo secneuqesnoc eht serongi laudividni nA
.eveileb ton did ylpmis ynam os dna
,dias yehT .neht tsael ta
sretroppus dna seilla reh dna ,thguof ehS   .dehcram ehs dna
,reilrae elttil a nrob neeb namow siht daH
,nroht detsiwt a ekil ,sworg ti
.dehctaw saw htap reh fo pets yreve ,erehT
.evah won uoy modeerf eht uoy evig ot decifircas saw tahw etaicerppa uoy taht dna
ecaf sih ot deil yehT .degeiseb
,desu eb ot tnaem erew syaw gnignahc eht taht meht ecnivnoc ot gniyrt
,ot denitsed saw ti
,emit eht ta ,detaert erew syaw gnignahc eht dna
.ereht regnol on saw taht ymra na fo ytefas eht ot teg ot gnipoh ,kcab llef eH
.nwohs yltnenimorp eb eye gnissim dna
.deraeppa ti reverehw decafed egasiv sih
.desare eb reven nac taht mrah sesuac dertaH
erom gnihton rof dehsiw seimra htob taht wenk ehS
.noitaived morf eerf dlrow a
.deddon ,hsipeehs ,yob ehT
.tfel evah dluoc ehs ,neht nevE
,reh fo deksa saw taht lla did ehS
.htap eht fo gninnigeb eht dekram taht seert eht neewteb kaerb llams eht ta nogard eht tsap gnikool
..ssap secitsujni eseht tel ylpmis ot reh dnoyeb saw ti ,dlihc yM
.sesuac eh mrah erom eht
,dlot saw ehs ,noitaived ynA
.rewop eruces ot dertah fo semalf eht naf ot etatiseh ton lliw ohw
tnemezidnargga-fles nwo rieht rof srehto truh ot gnilliw enoemos no tcilfni nac ew tnemhsinup tsal dna
,dlihc ym ,uoy htiw sniamer esle gnihton fi dnA
.sevlesmeht tcetorp tonnac ohw esoht tcetorp ot og tsum ew hcihw ot shtgnel eht dna
.spihsdrah nwo reh esae ro
spahrep sa ,dedne ti tuB
,sllaftip ,serutaerc lufraef
,mih ta daeh sti dekcoc nogard ehT