.mottob sti gninroda laes layor eht htiw etelpmoc
.ereht ,thgir saw dlobok ehT
,meht neewteb drows dehtaehs a erob owt tsal ehT
”!dliub ot modgnik a evah eW !sehcir ruo gnirB
.moolb ni saw drahcro elppa eht dna
.evom ylerab dluoc ehs yldab os gnitcirtsnoc dna sselesu
,resolc dekool eh nehW
.smoor reh ot pu reh nees ev’I .ris ,seY“   ”?ylurT“
”.meht htiw rethguad ruoy thguorb ev’yeht eveileb od I dna
.dlobok dael eht ta kool resolc a koot ehS ”?reh fo tahW“   ”.lrig
.elam a erans dluoc tahw saw taht won
.tuo emac snogard eht
?enod eh dah tahW
,kcab gnikool tuohtiw ,nehT
,erusaem yna saw erutats s’llefremoS ssiM elttiL fI
”.sdnal egavas nretsew eht morf si rehtom sih syas rehtaF
.dnah eno ni tuo ssalg lluf-flah eht gnidloh ,denrut eH
,reh htiw dednocsba s’taht nogard eht morf rethguad ym fo nruter efas eht roF
.yadretsey ytnuob eht detsop tsuj ylno I
noillim a flah revo mialc yal daetsni dluow sllefremoS eht
.yad sih nekrad ot noitartsurf elttil rehtona tsuj saw tI
,dnal nwo sdlobok woN
”!etunim eno tiaw woN“
.gnuts neeb d’eh fi sa kcab dnah sih dellup eH
”-ot nwod egayov reh rof navarac rehtona egnarra I elihw ot-nees llew si ehs taht ees esaelP
.erutats lanoitnevnocnu rieht fo sseldrager
.sredurtni emoclewnu eht ta seye reh deworran ehS
.elbakatsimnu dna euqinu saw
.ruof uoY !uoY“
.deliaw ehS ”!oN“   ”-
.sthgink deen toN .ssecnirp deen toN
.nmad nmad nmaD .nmaD
eniuneg era yeht taht setats taht rettel a evah tcaf ni od seoreh eseht taht ,drol ym ,sraeppa tI“
.oot ,hcnul sih htiw seirrehc evah ot gniog saw eH
,thgir er’uoY !niT“ .deliaw dna
.stserof hgih eht ni seert fo spot eht ssorca dna swodaem niatnuom no delwarps meht dnif d’uoY
.noos semoc eh epoh od I ,hO“
,yrotirret nogard emirp fo serca dnasuoht derdnuh owt ylraen fo drol eht saw eH
”-esaelp uoy dluow woN .od uoy seY .seY“
.smaes eht ta cirbaf eht gniniarts
”.saw tnemeerga eht eveileb od I ,yrrac nac uoy fo eno sa yvaeH“
.dlobok elttil a tsuj er’uoY“ .taps ehS
.neht ezigolopa tsum I ,lleW“
!ovyeT si eman siH
.tibbiT dna kaD sthginK !kiliK mA“
?htrow lla ti saw tahw tub
.edroh reh rof dlog dna smeg deirrac dah trac reH
,sdlobok eht ot denetsil I
!ereh fo tuo reh teg dna lrig sselesu taht ekaT
,rehtaew gniksab saw tI
.gnilpas hcrib detnalp ylwen a tsniaga kcab denael
”.eciton tub pleh t’nac I“
.eurt sI .dlobok ylliS“   ”…etam a tuohtiw—
.eciton ot ton deraeppa dlobok ehT
.elims deye-ssorc a htiw kcab ssalg eht dednah dna ti delahni eH
?esroh a edir yehT“
.ti htaeneb selcsum erom neve revo gnidils yllautca saw erutalucsum eht taht ees dluoc ekud eht
.pu hctac ot tnemom a dnim sih evag snoilleh delacs elttil eht morf yawa gninruT
”!piY .erif sehtaerB .selacs giB“
”.noisiced a ot emoc ev’I ,rehtaF“
.dnah dehctertstuo sih morf ssalg tohs eht deveirter dna
,ecnanimod reh wohs ,htgnerts reh wohS
”.llams yrev era uoy tahT“
.elytsefil delbuort s’ekuD eht fo ytivarg eht fo tpecnoc on dah yehT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.yltcaf-fo-rettam detats llefremoS ssiM elttiL
.sselgninaem yllautriv dna
.nori saw pirg reH
.tniop a dah ti timda ot dah eH
,niaga ni daeh sti knud dluoc dlobok dael eht erofeB
.’gniht‘ reh yllaer saw srettel latipac ni draeh flesreh gnikaM .duol
,devomer saw gniremmay sseltniop reh dna lrig ehT .yawa dekcab dna
,nedrag desolcne llams sih otno denepo rood A
”.ssecnirp a fo daetsni ssehcud yllis emos htiw ma I ereh dna
.srehtael ni dlobok eht ot revo yaw sti dehsols ssalg eht dna ,elbbauqs a saw ereht
.deraor lagihromoknA ”!TEIUQ eb tsuJ“
,gniknaps prahs a rof rethguad sih hctac ot tuo dehcaer ekud ehT
erehT .ecaep evitalpmetnoc ,teiuQ
.sniatnuom eht morf neeb evah tsuM
.dedoow ylivaeh dna yggarc saw tI
.noitacilpmoc rehtona neeb dah llefremoS ssiM elttiL   .yrwoD
,egdirbaeS .thgiR“ .ti denrae d’eH
”.nosrep ekuD .rM ,nogard a ot derapmoc uoy naht rellams hcum toN“
.retal siht terger ot gniog saw eH .ydnarb eht htiw
,egdirbaeS !eniF !thgirlA“
.dnabsuh eb-ot-noos dna dehtorteb reh—
…reh pihsrow ot geb dluow nogard eliriv yna dna
ssecnirp a tuohtiw ,llits tuB“
.snwot dna segalliv ni gnuh erew steehsdaorb dna seciton ytnuoB
.nrehtron dna egral—
.yad doog a gnivah ton saw llefremoS ekuD
a hcus erew snogard eht dna
,sserd yllirf ,kniP
.trid eht ni pmur sih ot delbmuts eh dna
”!yrlavac detnuom s’yehT !piy ,deen oN“
”!woleb dnuorg lla dnA“
,edalg eht otni deppets ruatonim s’dlobok ehT
.sgel yldnips sti no decnad redael ehT
.tcartnoc elttil taen a hcus neeb d’tI
.yrrac dluoc eh sa yvaeh sa dlog fo gab a dna dnal fo lecrap a detnarg eb dluow mih ot rethguad sih nruter dluoc ohw eH
!ecnirp eht saw tI .delahni ehS
.pets sih ni desuap eH
.yltpmorp os dnopser ot enoyna detcepxe t’ndah I
.ti koot llefremoS ekuD
.edis eht ot daeh reh dekcoc dlobok ehT ”.eurT“
.meht htiw dum ni deggard yehT
.moc.enilnoyxof.www
,xelfer dennuts htiw dna
,tsael ta—ereht devil eno on
.lrig namuh eht fo esuaceb emac eW“ .dias redael ehT
.sdoom rieht rof snosaer detacilpmoc dah nem detacilpmoc dna ,nam detacilpmoc a saw eH .t’nsaw eh tuB
,reh htaeneb paeh elbatrofmoc a otni delip senots suoicerp-imes dna
”.ecnatniauqca ruoy ekam ot desaelp ma ,he ,I“   ”.kiP si eriuqS
)noitacilpmoc suoiverp ees(
.noitseuq nwo rewsna uoy ebyam tuB
.edalg noitatidem dellif-nus sih dnuora delworp eh sa enotselbboc esool a ta dekcik yldednim-tnesba llefremoS ekuD
?saw yllautca yad eht emoselbuort woh tsuj tneserper yletarucca erom tatibah lacol eht t’ndluoc ,yhw ho ,yhW
.ezis reh rof tif doog a saw tI
.drol ym ,seoreH eht tneserp I yaM“
,taoc-hcnert a ni sdlobok eerht yllautca si eh taht seined ohw
!noitan dlobok ti eralceD
cigam od t’ndluoc ehS
.evorg noitatidem sih otni deppets ssiM elttiL nehT
.reh retfa kool ot nairanilpicsid a dna fehc deniart-llew a gnirih yb devlos evah dluoc eh taht—taf t’nsaw ehS
.deggurhs ekud ehT ”.ssse-Y“
.yltcerid meht ta kool dluoc ehs os
”.ti htaeneb dnal dnA .thgiR
”?noitcerid lareneg eht ni meht tnioP“
.tnadnecsed tcerid a saw ehs
.revo ekat ot tnaw d’eh ,elam a dah ehs fI !nmaD
.erif htaerB .yldaeD
.seye reh detniuqs nogard ehT
ralos eht fo thgil gnorts eht ni taht peed os
.tsiaw sih sa hgih sa pu emac neve meht fo enoN
.yrrehc fo ffihw tnetop eht ffo evag dna
.ffo flesmih dehsurb dna doots llefremoS ekuD
,rood eht fo yaw eht fo tuo dehsup saw egdirbaeS sa hcnurc a saw erehT ”!nitraM
,xaw fo hctolps llams a saw mottob eht nO
.toh nwod gninihs saw nus eht dna gnirps fo elddim eht saw tI .nus eht—eno roF
lerdnaK yb ”srerutnevdA“
.rieh fo tnuoma cifilorp ylurt a dah eh ,ssam yb ylerup derusaem uoy fi tub ,dlihc ylno dna tsrif sih saw ehS .lleW
,tnarg dnal eht fo ezis eht yficeps t’ndid tI
.ni deppets egdirbaeS dna
.der dna neerg yltsom erew sllihtoof eht ni ereh sdlobok ehT
.dnal mraf sa ti demialc setatse sih fo enon
.did yeht esruoc fO
.yllautca ,tluciffid erom ti ekam dluow ti ,slleH
.keew citamuart a dah sah ssecnirp elttil ym erus m’I“ .deggurhs eH ”.hO“
.thgiew s’dlobok eht rednu tneb tI
”?ti fo wonk uoy dluow tahW“   ”.riapsed t’noD“
”!ekatsim elbirroh a saw sihT !oN .oN“   -dna
,pu dewohs thgink tsrif eht neve erofeb ssecnirp eht tae ot locotorp dab saw tI
.gnilpas hcrib eht fo stoor eht ta nwod tas llefremoS ekuD
?eman sih wonk uoy oD“   -
.flesruoy eb ot deen tsuJ
ralos gniniojda eht otni deklaw ssiM elttiL   ”.yhtrow s’eh fI
:yojne esaelP
,drawer suoinegni na neeb dah tI
.plug gnissih elgnis a ni ydnarb eht delahni dna ssalg tohs eht otni daeh sti dekcud tI
.htiw doog erew snogard rehto sgniht ynam ta doog t’nsaw ehS
,nepo deppans seye reH
,yltnerehocni deknilb llefremoS ssiM elttiL
”?sgniw htiw tsaeb egraL“   ”.seY
.gnihtemos gnirebmemer fi sa ,etatiseh ot demees dlobok ehT ”!eroM“
ot txen kni eht ni dnah sti dettalps dlobok eht dna
dluoW‘ .thgiarts ,yad elohw a rof taht ekil no gniog neeb dah namuh diputs ehT
.evorpmi ton did ehcadaeh siH
.noitacol sti ron
.tnemom a rof rehto hcae gnoma delbbauqs sdlobok ehT
”!ereh ysub elttil a m’I ,ees nac uoy sA
!neeuQ“   ”-ton s’taht ,tiaW“
”?ereht teg uoy pleh ereh nogard elam gnivah lliw woH
.smoor reh fo tuo yllanif saw ssiM elttiL ,hO   ”!rehtaF“
”!tnemyap desimorP .rethguad dnuoF“
.dewollof taht ecnelis eht hguorht tuc eciov lartuen s’egdirbaeS
”.daeh ruoy ot og ti tel t’noD“
.srettel latipac reh morf kcab degnirc sdlobok ehT ”?TAHW“
.meht rof ton drowS“
.esruoc fO“   ”!ssenisub ruo si dnal htiw od ew tahW“
!nitraM .su tcepxE
.tuo pils ti tel ot derutluc llew oot saw eh tub ,nimrev
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.sdnal sih fo snoitacramed eht fo eno sa desu saw sepols sti morf nwod dewolf taht revir eht ,hturt nI
gniprihc erew sdrib ehT
etairporppanu yleritne si sihT .won thgir pu naelc dna moor ruoy ot oG !ssiM elttiL“
!noinimoD !rewoP !ytuaeB !seY“   ”!niatnuom ym fo pot eht morf ees nac I sa raf sa rof gnihtyreve elur lliw I !neeuq nogard a eb lliw I“ .thguoht dna deppots lagihromoknA   ”?smodgnik-fo-regavar-taerg ,eb ot tnaw uoy tahW
”!noitan dlobok fo kiliK neeuq fles eralceD
”.drol ym ,selbats eht ni ruatonim a evah yehT“ .ni
”.romra gninihs fo stius rieht ni tnallag eb ot desoppus era secnirp dehtorteb woh tuoba lla daer ev’I
!dnal nwo fo srelur won sdloboK
?elam a htiw deen uoy tahw tuB“
-   .ti fo erus saw eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”?tneserper uoy od ohW“
.hguone llew gnola delddum ehs hguoht ,reylf trepxe na t’nsaw ehS
nwo sih no llefremoS ekuD gnivael
,yawa sniatnuom morf eno ecitne ot evah I
.niaga ’ssecnirp‘ eht ta dekool ehS
.tneidebo saw rethguad sih tsael tA
.nekat neeb dah rethguad sih
”.eniuneg eb ot sraeppa tI
.reppoc dna nit htiw decalper eb ot
.snroh gniknird euqitna owt erew ti ot deulg dna
.flesmih ot timda ot dah eh
”.dnah ym rof ksa nac eh kcab emoc I nehw ebyaM
,srehtael s’retnuh ni rehtona saw taht dniheB
.sdnal sih ssorca tcide eht edam d’eh ,daetsnI
tonim eht ekat uoy dluow
?ereht ebirt ruoy sI ?hO“   ”!oot
”.yrrac nac uoy sa gab a ni dlog hcum sa dna ,etatse ym morf dnal fo lecrap a gnireffo m’I
.niamod sih fo redrob eht no saw cihceD tnuoM
.snwal derucinam ylluferac sih ni gnikcilorf erew reed dna
”.taht ot tif ees dluoc I .se-eY“
,noitulos a rof dnuora tsac ehS
”…rieht roF“   ”.tnuom rieht roF
.gniruop sih ni deppots llefremoS ekuD   ”!piY“   ”-a s’tI
,sdlobok eht fo eno ot kcab rettel eht dednah eH ”.eeS …I“
”?I t’ndid ,did I ,seY“
?sdlobok sserdda neve enoemos seod woH
.edalg lufecaep eht otni dehsarc dna reltub evitnetta eht dnuora delttucs yehT .deedni did yehT
.tuons reh no dnah dimit a tlef ehS
…suomrone rehtar reh dna reh htiw ffo edam dna navarac reh ni tseretni nekat t’ndah
!stnatropmi ton eziS“
”.detnuom er’yeht fi neve ,drows eht dloh ot deen llits yeht ,yawynA
.ssiM elttiL em llac t’noD“
,sgab ytfeh owt htiw denruter nitraM
niaga dewob dlobok ehT
.deR naidnA a saw tI
.ot ees ot noitatuper sih dah eh tub ,serutaerc elttil lufwa eht drawer ot ehtaol saw eH
,noitadnemmoc fo rettel laiciffo na saw tI
)?tibbiT ti saw ro( kaD dellac d’ehs eno eht ,eno rehtonA ”!puY“
”?sey ,ytrap ruo fo ynA“
,nam relpmis a neeb dah llefremoS ekuD fI
.nepo ralos sih ot rood eht draeh eh nehw elppit gninrom a flesmih gniruop saw eH
,lerdnaK yb ”srerutnevdA“
…fo tnih a htiw ,dloG
.tnemom a rof etanimur taht tel llefremoS ekuD
.edis sti ta notab elpmis a deirrac dna ebor kcalb elpmis a erow—
daeh reh derewol dna delwocs ehS
.deid dah namuh eht spahrep thguoht lagihromoknA ,tsrif tA .deppotS
,oreh nikpmub yrtnuoc nwot-llams ruoy ot sehcir saw tI
.dezilaer nosrep lamron ruoy naht reivaeh hcum saw dlog ,rehtruF
.syad tneicna eht ni sniatnuom eht derednaw taht
.llefremoS ekuD rof yrusaert eht ni tned a ekam ylerab dluow ti tub
.dewob dna deretne
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.yks-eht-fo-ydal ,swen llI“
?ydnarb rof erac uoy dluoW
.niaga ti desolc neht
sessecnirp diputs edulcni t’ndid yeht emit siht dna
,rehtaew gniksab saw ti nehw dna
.tsdim ruo ni snaretev denedrah hcus dah ew erawa t’nsaw I
gnieb ta doog ylralucitrap ,revewoh ,saw ehS
.sgniw reh delrufnu dna doots ehS
”srerutnevdA“ saw sihT
.sesunis sih tsniaga sbmuht tup llefremoS ekuD
,flesmih dednimer eh ,dnoceS   .noitacilpmoc
drow eht demrof htuom siH
?sebirt nrehtron eht morf efiw a nekat reve eh dah yhW
”.nruter reh no nosrep ni uoy ees ot ton derreferp ehs yas ot yrros m’I
,seY“   ”.ralos ym ni sdlobok era erehT“   ”?drol ym ,seY“
”?tfil nac eh dlog hcum woh tuo erugif ew litnu sgab tsioh mih evah dna erusaert eht ot nitraM ekat uoy dluow ,yrroS—
.enola yrrac ot meht fo eno rehtie rof yvaeh oot
.dnatsrednu ton od I“
.sdlobok eht no delttes dna
,mottob eht ot eman sih delwarcs llefremoS ekuD
.sdlobok fo elpuoc a ylno saw tI .on
.reh ta depwag llefremoS ekuD
.reltub sih morf repap eht debbarg dna liat delacs a revo deppets llefremoS ekuD ”!ereh ti eviG“
.maerd ot ylno fi ,hO .elbissop saw tI
.eceipdaeh reh devomer raor rehtona ta tub
.etam a yub t’ndluoc edroh a tub ,elbatrofmoc saw ti ,eruS
.mih dniheb repap fo gnilknirc eht saw erehT
,egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.sdlobok revelc dekil ehS .revelC .elameF
,htiw rotisiv reh tsaor ot tuoba saw ehs emalf fo trons eht tuo dehguoc ehs ,yllautcA
.ylddif oot saw ti—
.ffo si tnemegagne eht taht nosrep ’ecnirP‘ taht lleT“
.dnim sih dessorc ylno d’ti fi sa ,yllausac derutnev eH
.nworc eht fo sredasurc sa ti gniraeb srerutnevda eht gnitic
”!ki’keeD tnuoM fo sepols nwo won dloboK !laiciffo sI“   .ti
.etalsnart ot mih rof tnemom a koot tI .desuap llefremoS ekuD   ”.ki-keeD tnuoM“ .ylprahs mih ta pu dekool eno dael eht nehT
.eman hsi-dlobok yrev a t’nsaw nitraM ?nitraM
,noitseuq tsrif sih elfits ot dah eh ,reh htiw ffo nwolf dna rethguad sih pu dekcip dah nogard a taht dlot neeb tsrif d’eh nehW
,reltub sih ,egdirbaeS
!dengis tcartnoC“   ”-I .ecin s’tahT
.ti morf deraeppasid ssalg ydnarb eht dna ,niaga tuo dnah sih dleh llefremoS ekuD   ”?esaelP“ .derewolg
”?woH“ neeb dah hcihw
.elgnit niatrec taht tog ehs ,neht tuB
.esruoc fO .seY .daeR“
pu dehcaer dlobok tsesolc ehT
,tenicsab leets a saw daeh reh nO
”!ecnecifingam ruoy ,eno oN“
”…ton ,srerutnevda denosaes deen I ,egdirbaeS“
”-nogard a tsniaga tub
.llew yrev gnidaer ton meht tuoba trap eht derebmemer eH
?sey a neeb taht daH
”.ytnuob ym daer ev’uoy ylsuoivbo ,lleW“
.ecaep ni tfel saw nogard eht dna
,noitareneg a nihtiW
.ylsuovren detfihs seye s’dlobok dael ehT
)revlis yltsom( snioc fo sdnasuoht erew erehT
.htuom reh otni pu ti gnuws dna walc eno htiw ti thguac nogard ehT
?tnaw uoy od tahW“
”-yap ot gnilliw m’I ,dias teehsdaorb eht sa ,woN“
”.ekud laicnivorp ,llams ,diputS .ekud a rehtaf reH
.od ot tahw em llet ot nam a deen t’nod I taht denrael dna
.selcsum dah selcsum sih neve ,lleH
”.tey ssem siht egavlas ot elba eb ll’I ebyaM
.ddo s’tahT ?seiranecreM“
.gnimoc rof uoy knahT“
emit erom eno tsuj htuom reh denepo ehs fI
,esnam sih fo tuo nworc eht fo sredasurc dezirohtua worht tsuj t’ndid erutats sih fo ekud A
.selacs eulb cillatem krad htiw sklof ekil-drazil elttil erew yehT
,ralos eht morf meht delttub reltub siH
,seert deppilc ylesolc sih ni gnignis erew sdrib esruoc fO
,hctah ot snalp erew
-saw tI !yerp reh saw tI
,denruter evah sdlobok ruoy ,drol yM“
.rethguad s’gnik t’nsi derutpac ev’uoy lrig ehT
.delwocs ekud ehT
”.yawa saw I elihw tol a denrael I“
.egde ot egde ,emarf eht dellif epahs suortsnom a dna
,kcab mih werht ehS
.terger ni ecaf sih derevoc ekud ehT
.ki’keeD tnuoM rednu evil ebirt dlobok llA“
.sse-nogard suoegrog uoy tub
.yad doog a neeb ton dah tI
.syad remmus cillydi htiw elbuort eht saw tahT
.tsae eht morf gnildees a sa detropmi dah rehtaf sih eert eht morf
.depoh d’eh naht retteb saw tI
…ssecnirp a ton fI
?esrow yna teg ti dluoc woh tub
”?ti enim ot nalp uoy od ,tahW“
.niaga yaled egnarts taht saw erehT
.desserpmi m’I ,timda tsum I
.sbos dna sraet otni tuo ekorb secnirp evitpac eht ,raor suorednuht eht tA
.nogarD .piY !piY“
.t’ndluow ti ,yllautcA
.detatiseh ekud ehT
,kcab denrut redael ehT
.dnatsrednu ton dlobok diputs ,mu ,dnA
.flesreh detartsorp dlobok ehT
”.suoixonbo dna duol tsuj sessecnirP
.esrow teg dluoc ti woh s’taht ,lleW .hO
.egatireh ym tuoba nrael ot htron gniog m’I
”!dnal desimorP !dnal dnA“
.srerutnevda detah eH
-   .selam suoniur ro
.meht fo ruof erew erehT
nogard eht fi ,si tahT .serca
.niatpac draug eht morf meht nelots d’ehs ekil dekool taht srehtael ni toof ot daeh dekced saw ehS
.eugnot gnirettalc ,gnissih rieht ni sdlobok eht neewteb noitasrevnoc saw erehT
,dedaf dlog fo etsat eht ,tnemom a tsuj retfA .oN
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.reh dnif ot sthgink sih dnes ot gnik eht rof lamron saw ti thguoht I
.elbirroh saw derutpac gnitteG
”!llet ew dna kcab oG
.won rof tsael ta ,lleW
,sdnal sih fo trap yllacinhcet saw ti hguoht nevE
.borht daeh sih edam taht sdlobok eht morf reehc gnissih a saw erehT
”.arait ruoy em evig ,lriG“
.flesreh gnitartsorp yldimit
…saw ehs daetsni ,oN
”-dlog fo gab a ,neht ,lleW“
.llew sa thgin tluciffid a eb ot gniog saw tI
.revoc ot seloh-rae lanretxe dah ehs dehsiw neerg eht lagihromoknA
ekorb reltub siH
.yllacitamotua ydnarb fo erusaem rehtona deruop sdnah siH   ”.esaelP“
…devirra dah rethguad sih nehw tuB
.liam gninihs erow taht srehto owt erew edis eht ot dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.nwod eltnam eht evoba gnuh dah eh drows lainomerec eht koot dna
.emoc ot meht rof deksa dah eh ,llitS
.snogard emos nees evaH“   ”.dnatsrednu
.gnidaer ta doog on ereh kiP yas ,tuB
.specib evissam sih no rehto hcae revo gnidils selcsum evissam
”.ytnuob ruoy ot esnopser nI
!rial reh deretne dah enoemoS
htuom reh morf noitaroced gnidneffo eht taps ehS
.dlobok elamef eht ylno saw ti tub
,kcab ssalg eht dednah tI
.flesreh wef a deyolpme ehS
.nogard tnecifingam a era uoY
.raewtoof lacitcarpmI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,lerdnaK yb
.htrig suoiverp sti eciwt ot nellows dah redrob nrehtron siH .dnal eht dnA
.hguone gnorts s’eh ,si taht ,fI“
”!yrrac nac ew sa yvaeH“
”.niaga neppah reven ll’ti os ecitcarp dna nrael ot gniog m’I
,emehcs ot semehcs dna
.hteet prahs dna llams yrev dewohs taht elims a demaeb dlobok dael ehT   ”.tsdim
.edroh reh no despalloc lagihromoknA
?pu tuhs reve ssecnirp eht dluoW
.mih teg ll’eW“   ”.nitraM s’ohW“
.yad doog a neeb evah dluow ti
”?duol tuo su lleT
.rettel elbanmad sti htiw gnicnad saw redael dlobok ehT
.ytaert eht neeb dah ereht ,esruoc fO
?rood tnorf sih no thgir ,noitan dlobok A
.esnes edam ehs tsael tA
”?ti yrrac ot eno eht eb lliw uoy fo eno hcihw ,oS“
”.drol ym ,esruoc fO“
.yllis diputS .dlobok elttil yllis ma I ,thgir uoY
.sgniht yhsiuqs ,tfos hcus er’yehT
ti otni dessobme laes layor eht dna
,mih thgif ot evah d’ehs nehT
hA“   .kcab s’reltub eht dniheb morf detpure noitamalcxe duol A ”!mehA“
.sdnal sih fo trap tnatropmi llits tub llams a yawa evig ot evah d’eh thguoht d’eH
.ytrap gnirutnevda fo trap lufgninaem dna tnatropmi nitraM“
.dias eno rehtonA ”.nitraM“
mih ot thguorb tsafkaerb sih ni seirrehc dah neve d’eH
!hguaF ?’taht od ecnirp eht dluoW‘ ’?siht eb ecnirp eht
.latem tsuj saw tI
.yad elbirroh rehtona saw tI
dnalemoh s’rehtom reh retfa koot ehS
!suoretsoperp saw tahT
setatse sih morf raf saw ,hguoht ,sihT
.ebirt snroH-owT eht fo ahgnA si eman yM
”…dna spam meht evig uoy dluow
”.drol ym ,uoy ot kaeps ot hsiw sdlobok eht eveileb od I .hah-
nepo ronam eht fo rood tnorf eht dekcik ehs
.raelc era smret eht ,lleW“
.sregnif sih morf ti dehctans ohw
.emuser dluoc yclamron emos tsael tA
neht ylno saw tI
.detlusnoc saw pam a dna pu nettirw saw tcartnoc A
.selpmet sih dleh eH
.edroh nogard eht fo sllaw eht fo ffo deohce seirc gnikcarw s’namuh ehT
”.egdirbaeS“   .deppots eH
?gnihsad eb ll’eh kniht uoy oD
.dlrow eht otni tuo dellorts dna
”.selacs-eht-fo-ssertsim-ho ,reh dnif ot seiranecrem gnirih rehtaf s’lrig ehT“
”.cihceD tnuoM fo sepols eht no dnal emoS .sey ,seY“
,sdnah sti ni repap delpmurc eht devaw dlobok ehT
”.seoreh eht era yehT .ris
.kcalb deraeppa tsomla ti
!citoxe os s’tahT
,egduj tseb ton ebyaM
”?tniop eht s’tahw ,hO .ssehcud a s’ehs
kiP dellac ehs eno ehT
”!daer ,ereH !rettel evaH“
.tuo yad ynnus a saw tI
.lluf-flah ti dellif dna draobedis eht morf ssalg rehtona koot eh ,edis efas eht no eb oT
.pu tes tnemnrevog teg ew sa noos sa yrasimme dnes lliW
.suoregnaD .lufituaeB
,htuom reh denepo ehS
.ti no laes layor eht sah ti dna ,ym hO .srerutnevda
!detcartnoC !dengiS !deergA“   ”-tuB“   ”.ssob seY“
,saw eh naht rellat daeh a saw rethguad sih taht mih ot derrucco ti taht
”.nogard a yb nekat neeb s’ehs erawa era uoY
.gniruop deunitnoc eH ”.esruoc fo ,hA“
nos s’rehtaefeldniP droL teem ot htuos eht ot yaw reh no neeb dah ehS
”!noissim eht stog eW !piY“
redael rieht saw ti demussa eh ro—redael ehT
.emoh kcab nogard-elam ruo tisiv emoc yehT
”?elam a yb flesruoy gnirusaem rehtob yhW
.delbmur ruatonim ehT ”.ssob sknahT“   ”.ytrap
.ecaf reh ssorca skaerts dekram dna erehwemos tniap eulb emos dnuof d’ehS
.rethguad ym eveirter ot deen ll’uoy tsrif tuB“
snatit dna stnaig fo sdnegel dna shtym dah yeht ,htron eht nI .nrehtroN
,eulb layor ,krad a erew selacs stI
”!drows nwo rieht tsioh neve t’nac owt esoht tuB“
.redluohs eht ssorca redaorb yltnacifingis dna
.daetsni mih thguac dna pu dehcaer ehs tub
,sessalg tohs eht ni ydnugrub saw tI
,seY“   ”.trams sdloboK
,sthgink deirf-peed dna ,sessecnirP
.selam elbigile dnasuoht a evah tsum ned ruoY
…tsuj esion eht nehT