.tsiser ton ot azilE htiw daelp ot deirt ti hguoht sa
,ecarbme thgit a mih evig ot drawrof dehsur azilE
.daeh sih koohs revird ehT
dehsimaf saw rehtorb redlo reh detcepsus azilE
!tihs kcaj ees t’nod I“
revo deppoh ylkciuq nam eht ,revewoH
”!esimorp I ,yltpmorp evael ll’ew
.nem eht fo seciov eht draehrevo dna
.pu kcab doots erutaerc eht erofeb
erow syawla rehtorb reh engoloc a fo tnecs eht pu dekcip eson reh tub taht ylno toN
.etingi ot nugeb dah kcurt eht erom
,nekcihc deirf dloc no dekcans yehT
srotaderp ybraen detcartta dah doolb reh taht desseug ehS
htiw triks reh debbarg ,raewrednu reh no denwad ylkciuq azilE
,dnatsrednu t’nod uoY“  ”.esimorp I
,seirots laisrevortnoc erom reh ni egludni nac ehs woh saw
pil sih revo regnif a tup maharbA
,ecarbme eht morf yawa ekorb ylluf eh erofeB
.fo erawa yletamitni erew yeht sdrazah eht htiw laed ot evah dluow ehs ,azilE roF
.yob eht no eye na peek dna pu tuhs tsuJ
.deilper redael kcap ehT ”.og lla ti tel
.tuo teg ew nehw noitcartsid a esuac ll'I“
.dooh rieht no sdnah htob htiw elcihev rieht fo tnorf ni doots dna
noitcartsid eht fo egatnavda koot ehS
,snoitats sag nwod desolc owt ssorca emoc dah yeht retfa dnA
.stnemhsilpmocca s’azilE rof edirp fo snoisserpxe suoirav demrof dah lla yeht
”.yb semoc ffirehs a erofeb ecalp siht evael dna
.revird eht degdun deT ”!ti no petS
,reh fo tnorf ni thgir gnitnap dna
,kcab deppets eh sA
,tniop egatnav reh morF
”!em dellik ev’dluoc tI
ecaf sti no elims eninac ylkcis a saw erehT
.lamina suoiruc a eb ot ti demussa dna
”!stnemom wef a su evig tsuJ
,rehtorb reh htiw htuoy reh gnirud noitacav no tneps dah ehs nibac yzoc a ot skcabhsalf llams htiW
”?retsnom a otni reh gninrut saw reh evas ot yaw tseb eht thguoht uoY“
.kcurt gnideeps eht htiw pu thguac yllaudarg ehs sa
,hguoht feiler s’azilE oT
.owt rehto eht ffo thgif ot detpmetta dna
meht fo owt eht ta kcab derats yliratnemom erutaerc ehT
:ediced ot uoy ot ti tup eW
,rennam deltrats a ni mrof flowerew s’azilE ta pu derats dna
kcohs htiw denediw seye siH
”,serutaerc dnaldoow yracs yna htiw laed ot deen t’now uoy dna
.txen ekat ot etuor tahw wonk ot dedeen
,noihsaf evissimbus a ni nwod dedlof dah srae s’tsaeb ehT
tsif sih dehcnelc maharbA
.meht no lausiv tnatsnoc a deniatniam tub
.sdaor ippississiM doowkcab krad eht gnola seert llat eht hguorht ecreip yletauqeda dluoc
.ecneirepxe reh morf eurt kcurts dah sdrow eht tlef dah azilE
,snoitautis efil-naht-regral ni nemow naibsel
semuf yna fo noitacidni on saw erehT
.s’02 sih naht redlo on tsael ta
.meht rof ereht eb ot evah ew tub
”?maercs ot detrats eh yhw rednow I“
,kcab reh deklats revihs tnasaelpnu nA
,noisserpmi s’azilE oT
flesreh rof od dluoc ehs tsael eht ,ylimaf htiw elihw flesreh fo edis taht rehtoms ot decrof saw ehs fI
.tfihs thgin eht gnirud regnad laitnetop yna ot prahs deniamer dnim s'azilE ,ydob reh hguorht gnisruoc ados yragus htiW
.siht revo sag etsaw annog ton m’I“  .dedaelp azilE ”!su gniklats yletinifed si ereht tuo gnihtemos
,sivaD suiraD yb ”tfiG ehT“ si
.ecaf s'rekcatta eb-dluow eht tsniaga swalc reh hsals ot eno eerf rehto reh desu ehs
kciht reh hguorht decreip ot deirt dah niap prahs a
rueffuahc a saw eh taht nialpxe ot deirt eh
.gnihton ylbaborp s’ti os ,t’ndid ti tuB
niks htooms naht erom gnihton saw ereht litnu dedecer taoc ruf ehT
.detsetorp maharbA
.tah rueffuahc s’rehtorb reh htaenrednu sehcnul xobeohs rieht eveirter ot taeskcab eht otni debmilc ylsseldrow ehS
.ydob deirruf sti htiw azilE fo pot no dial dna decnuop gnieb evissam ehT  .dias tI ”,yrroS“
.slleb hcruhc tuo denword evah dluow ti taht
.krow fo hcraes ni htuos nwod diam eht gnikat saw eh dna
,rehtorb reh htiw hctaw thgin tsrif reh t’nsaw sihT
maharbA fo tnecs ehT
mih ot derepsihw dna rehtorb reh ot esolc denael azilE .demahsanu dna
.gnol rof deregnil t’ndah dna yenruoj sti no deunitnoc ti
.noisseccus kciuq ni gnimrofer dna
,esnopser eht yb deltrats elihW
sruoy si eciohc ehT
,sdnoces wef a retfA
.mih llik ot yrassecen saw ti tlef yeht yhw derednow dna
,rehtorb reh dettops dna taeskcab eht otni dereep azilE .edis thgir sti no gnulc gnihtemos hguoht sa detfihs kcurt eht fo thgiew eht
.wollof ot sliart suoivbo yna erew ereht fi ees ot sdoow eht dennacs ehS
,maharbA ,rehtorb reh esac ni pal reh no pam egral pu dedlof a tpek llits ehS
.edis ot edis morf kcurt eht reets yllacidarops ot detrats dah revird eht ,rehtorb reh eveirter dna edisa ti ssot dluoc ehs erofeB
.tlah a ot emac ylevissergga ti erofeb
.azilE fo espmilg a thguac dna rorrim weiv raer eht dekcehc deT
;daeh sih denilcer eH
,yenruoj rieht no elihW
semit lareves ti no dekconk nam ehT
.wodahs ni meht dekaolc dah hcihw
ytiliba siht fo tnetxe eht erolpxe ot tnaw I
.noisufnoc fo snoitcaer dexim erew emoS
.evila namuh yna evael reven eW“
.elcihev eht dna flesreh neewteb ecnatsid tcaxe eht ezilautpecnoc ot reh dewolla sesnes reh fo llA
.ecnadiug s’redael kcap eht thguos ehs
.laem reh hsinif dluoc ehs erofeb tsujda ot seye s’azilE fo setunim wef a koot tI
”?no ’niog s’tahW“
.taht ton s’tI“  .deksa maharbA
,erats yci detartsurf sih tuohtiw nevE
daeha no sserp ot decrof tlef maharbA
.daor eht fo edis eht otno revo dellup ti sa
!uoy fo htob eht ,rac eht
,tfihs hctaw thgin eht rof deraperp ehs sA
spil s’maharbA depacse hgis detsagrebbalf A
”!nwod uoy kcart em depleh dna em deucser yehT“
.rac eht sdrawot detlob dna ,sdnah htob
.ereht llits erew seye gniremmihs eht
.yawyna worromot snaelrO weN tih ot tuoba er’ew ,lleW“  .deilper ehS
.meht hcaorppa ot detrats dna
.etoyoc a ro flow a tsuj ylbaborP“
yrots s’thginoT dna
.rennam ralimis a ni eraps drow eht dias rehto eht elihw
.rehtorb reh eveirter ot ni debmilc ehs sa meht fo htob eht derongi ehS
.enod si enod s’tahw sa
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR  .stcejorp gnitirw erutuf rof
.flesreh ot thguoht azilE
,yks thgin eht ni flesti deretnec noom eht emit eht yB
larenuf s’rehtaf etal reh ta sevitaler tnatsid htiw gnilaed fo yteixna eht ffo gnittup tnaem ti fI
avreniM sa em ot refer yam uoY“
.ecalp ni revihs reh edam hcihw fo ycneuqerf eht
.ti daer ot deen elttil saw ereht sa
yek eht nrut dna sserp ot deunitnoc sdnah ykahs siH  .dias maharbA
.edis reh ta rehtorb reh htiw egakcerw eht fo tuo bmilc ot dedeecorp neht azilE  .noitisop latef
pu denethgiarts sredluohs sih htiw pu doots eH
.ylraluger ecneirepxe dluow ylekil kcap reh dna
”.eybdoog si siht won rof …oS
.seye sih revo ti tser ot
nugtohs eht rof deltserw maharbA
.ycavirp rof ssarg dliw emos otni deklaw dna rac eht morf tuo deppets ehs
.kcurt eht ni sknat artxe evah thgim I ?huh ,sag fo tuO“  .ereht dna neht thgir pu detca t’ndah rac eht dehsiw azilE ,ecnatsmucric rehto yna ni rovaedne lamron a elihW
.thgirla eb dluow ehs woh yevnoc ot detpmetta dna
reraelc deraeppa serutaerc ehT
”,od ot evah tsuj lliw rueffuahc ehT
.sdrow sih dootsrednu ehs wohs ot deddon azilE  .delffins eH
.yllacihtapelet deilper ehS
.trihs s’deT ta barg ot edisni dehcaer dna
.rehtorb reh rof erots ni srorroh eht rednuop ot tnaw t’ndid dnim reh ,delffins azilE
ti ot dnim on yap ot deirt ehS
.ria rof elggurts etarepsed a emaceb htaerb yreve sa
,sgnileef eurt reh fo erawa ydaerla saw rehtorb reh hguoht nevE
.deredro revird ehT
slaem rieht deinapmocca taht erutsiom fo ecnalbmes ylno ehT
.evila llits era uoy fo htob taht
neetnac retaw s’maharbA erew
.evael ot ecnahc ruoy dah lla’Y“
,rehtorb reh deirrac mra eno sA
.meht deppartne ylwols dna
.kcatta deliaf sih fo noitazilaer eht nopu
.ssarg llat eht yb derucsbo saw
.nees reve ev’I lamina yna naht retsnom a ekil erom dekooL
.tserof eht otni deraeppasid ti erofeb seye knalb gnilkraps fo riap eht dettops dna revo decnalg maharbA  .detniop ehS
,htuos nwod krow rof gnikool dna
rac eht trats ot detpmetta eH
,ekat ot htap hcihw no noisiced a ekam dluoc ehs erofeB
.thguoht ni peed erew ti hguoht sa noisserpxe na detcelfer reh erofeb retsnom eninac ehT
.evird otni rac eht tfihs ot detrats eh erofeb
.pu kool ot decrof saw eh dna
.tsurt dna pihsnoinapmoc dnuofwen fo yalpsid a ni
.elcihev eht edisni debmilc dna
.ecaf reh detnecca orfa yknik egral reH
.siht tnaw I tuB
ecalp ni koohs maharbA
.rehtegot deit teef dna sdnah sih
esaelp ,oN“  .deredro eH
,dnah a em dnel dna tuo emoc lla’y fI
.egassem tsal eno deyevnoc eh
”!ylimaf eno evah ylno eW
kcap reh ot sthguoht reh deyevnoc yllacihtapelet ylgniwonknu dah ehS
.eerht eht fo hcae htiw seye dekcol dna
.koob reh gnitelpmoc ot saw ehs esolc woh morf desruc azilE .flesreh eveiler ot egru eht tlef noos ehs
.revo dehcnuh ylthgils sredluohs dna kcab reh htiw
.sredluohs sih revo nugtohs gnol a dleh eno sa tuo detixe owT
.wapdnah lufrewop reh neewteb nopaew eht deppans dna tuo dehcaer azilE
.pil rewol reh tib ehs elihw yltcerid nam eht ta ecnalg ot ton deirt azilE .trats dluoc rac eht taht os
.draobhsad s’kcurt eht fo strap suoirav ssorca gnulf
sa redrum ydoolb demaercs kcurt eht edisni nem owt ehT
”?peels emos teg esaelp I nac woN
.knat rieht ni sag fo retrauq a htiw
osrot ralucsum yvaeh reh
ydob s'hctiM yb nekorb saw llaf s’rehtorb reh ,feiler reh oT
?esruc eht si hcihw
.evah dluow ti daed uoy detnaw yllaer ti fi ,kooL“
kcurt eht fo renroc tsellams eht ot detaerter neht eH
.daor eht ssorca deddiks dna edis sti no revo deppit dah kcurt eht
elims llams a dehsalf maharbA ,feiler reh oT
.tserof eht morf reh ta deknilb ylwols seye gniremmihs knalb emas eht
.ediskcab sih bur yllacitehtapme ot
.noitisop gnitser elbatrofmoc a fo hcraes ni saw ydob sih
spil s’eninac ehT
.lortnoc ot tluciffid elcihev eht edam ylno ffo reh ekahs ot tpmetta deliaf siH
.knalf reh ta srehto owt htiw
sivaD suiraD yb
,erofeb semit sseltnuoc desraeher sA
taes raer eht morf tah rueffuahc sih debbarg maharbA  ”.eb retteB“
edis ot edis morf dennacs elzzum reh sa decar dnim reH
,eciohc rehto on htiW
.sredluohs reh ot nwod detfird riah yknik larutan reh dna
.sredluohs sih deggurhs eH
”!yawa thgir evael lliw eW
.tseb ta sruoh
.reh ta kcab derats seye knalb gnilkraps fo stes eerht
,esirprus nwo reh oT
.gnidaer thgil emos htiw snoissap reh egludni si
?dedaeh erew owt eht erehw dna ,mih htiw saw ehs yhw
.laem ysae na rof ydob reh no tsaef ot dennalp yeht dna
denigami ehS
gnikaerb senob dna selcsum reh fo taht saw noitasnes eht ,reh oT
.noisiced a ot emac ehs erofeb
nades llams rieht otni deruop sthgil thgirb fo riap a
.ereh tuo dellik uoy teg t’ndluow I amam desimorp I“  .dednopser ehS
.yob erutan ,thgirlA“  .delkcuhc eH
saw sihT      ”!eno gnuoy
”?ti toG .kcurt eht ot mih yrrac em pleh annog er’uoy ,deT
edis s'azilE ot revo deklaw nugtohs eht htiw nam ehT  .dekrab eH ”!woN
.tfihsepahs ot nigeb reh dehctaw yeht sa redael kcap eht ot noitnetta reh denrut azilE
enobralloc reh no etib hguor a deviecer azilE ,gnol erofeB
.kcurt eht morf gnimaercs esnetni draeh ylneddus enoyreve sa
,stnemom wef a rof ecalp ni ezorf eh elihW
,yek eht fo nrut drah tsal eht htiW   .dedaelp maharbA
,noitamrofsnart eht detelpmoc ehs nehW
,thgirlA“  .dias eciov tnereffid A
.daor eht otno tuo ti evird ot gnol oot ekat dluow ti sa rac yb eelf ot noitpo driht a t’nsaw erehT
?lrig ,no uoy era tahW“
,levart rieht erofeb rewop siht dah yeht fi
,edam ehs eciohc hcihw rettam oN
seye fo stes eerht eht no lausiv tnatsnoc a tpek azilE
rac ruoy ot kcab daeh ylbaborp dluohs uoy
,kcap ruo ot emocleW“
nocaeb a sa detca nem eht dna
.teef reh no retsis sih teg ot deirt maharbA sa
uoy yb thgir enod syawla t’nevah I wonk I ,kooL“
delkcub sgel reH
erugif rellams ecno reH
.ydob s’azilE fo tser eht tuohguorht lla kram etib eht morf delevart niap gnibborht yreif a
rettiwt no mih wollof nac uoY.sevitcepsrep
.efil s’retsis ruoy evreserp ot gnisselb ruo dnetxe eW“
.senob derettahs dna
.reh morf laem eht detpecca eh sa
.mrof flowerew suoiverp reh morf yawa noitisnart ot nageb erugif suoicoref ecno eht sa
.evila mih gnitae flowerew eht fo sdnuos eht ot denetsil yldiviv lla yehT
,htgnerts dna enilanerda dnuof wen hcus htiW
.meht rethguals yllacifirroh dluoc taht serutaerc eseht fo sregnad nwonknu eht ecaf ot rO
.meht dnuora yrenecs eht ni koot yeht sa
.ydob s’retsis sih laecnoc ot ti desu dna trihs sih evomer ot detrats ydaerla maharbA
,stuobaerehw sih tuoba mih dellirg yehT
,em no era seye rieht fo lla ecnO
,revo dettauqs elihW
.dleihsdniw rieht ta lerrab eht detniop dna
mih ta seye gniremmilg dehsalf azilE
,yb esolc morf detaname lworg laruttug wol A
ffo deyarts owt sa
gniffins lamina na fo dnuos eht nopu ,revewoH
,ereh edisni yats uoy fi uoy teg annog sgnihtoN
.pu thguac ylkciuq reh dniheb ecno erew taht serutaerc eht deciton ehS
meht dessap kcurt 01C ytsur A
.noitcetorp fo mucidom emos rof
.tuo emoc ot kcurt eht edisni morf elpoep eht denoitom eH
knalp nedoow a naht rethgil on tlef nam eht
srettam hcus no llewd ot ton deirt ehS
?ereht tuo gniht taht tuoba tahW
taes rac eht ni detfihs azilE
azilE ot kcab denrut ti erofeb
.wodniw eht rewol ot maharbA denoitom dna
dekan meht erofeb doots ehS
.tuo lla’y pleh dna
.noitnetta s’azilE niag ot yllacihtapelet niaga nekops dah redael kcap ehT
peelsa maharbA fo tifeneb dedda eht dnA
.ris ,seigolopa yM“  .deksa eH
kcurt eht ot deulg seye rieht
nips revo dehcnuh dna
.kcab emoc ot ediced uoy fi uoy rof ereh eb syawla ll’I ,wonk tsuJ“
.tuo gninnur ot esolc ylsuoregnad erew yeht dna
.edis tfel reh dehctulc azilE sa
.dekan mih fo tnorf ni nwod deleenk retsis sih dehctaw maharbA
.edisni debmilc ehs dna segnih sti morf ffo rood eht deppir neht smra ythgim reH
,thgirpu nur ot elba saw ehs elihW
”.sneppah reve taht emit tsal eht eb lliw taht esimorp I .haey ,haeY“
.ycnargav dna gniretiol rof tserra s'nezitic rednu uoy fo htob eht ecalp annog m’I
.reh dniheb noitommoc a saw ereht
.sgel reh evom ot detrats dna deddon azilE
koob reh yawa dewots ehS
,rac sih ot kcab klaw maharbA dehctaw serutaerc eht fo lla ,guh rieht retfA
.edam evah dluoc ezalba tes nosrep a ylno taht maercs fo epyt A
”.nem esoht ot pots a tup ot ti desu uoy dna
dnik ni dednopser serutaerc rehto eht fo enon ,esirprus reh oT
,epacse ot htap a rof hcraes ot deunitnoc ehs nehw teY
.reh ta tuohs ot nageb dna
wodniw edis regnessap eht morf tsesolc eht eb ot deneppah deT
,tuo debmilc ehs erofeB
,evitcepsrep s’azilE morF
.nosirapmoc ni elap yeht hcihw tsniaga thgil eht ni sgniht niamer ereht ,eb yam krad eht ni sgniht eht emosraef revewoH  .remrahC eniuqE eht
sknat elbatrop rieht fo owt tsal eht deitpme ydaerla dah yehT
llat doots revird eht
,dednopser azilE erofeB
”?dloc uoY ?sis ,thgirla uoY“
.eye reh fo renroc eht thguac taht thgil fo yrekcirt a saw ereht
.tpels maharbA elihw gnidaer ot demotsucca emaceb ehs
,eye eht ni ti kool t’nod dna erutaerc eht diova uoy sa gnol oS
nam eht morf yalpsid ecidrawoc eht ,decneirepxe dah reh  dna maharbA gnihtyreve retfA
,nrut prahs eno retfA
yawyna htaed fo esuac larutan
”!meht gninioj redisnoc ylsuoires t’nac uoY
.thgis a hcus nuhs ot detpmetta dnim reh
.traeh reh nekcirts ylsuoiverp dah ssensuoixna revenehw efas leef reh edam taht ecalp a enigami ot deirt ehS .seye reh desolc dna daeh reh deddon azilE
.sevitcepsrep gniticxe dna wen ecneirepxe ot sredaer emirp ot yaw a sa gnitirw sesu ohw
egadnob morf mih deerf ehs ,ssensuoicsnoc niager ot detrats ylwols maharbA nehW
.flesreh denimaxe dna
)seirotsd2( ta egap yrrufoS sih dna goDdliWD2@
.emitnaem eht ni riah reh dexif dna
.sraet ni pu llew ot nageb seye sih fo renroc eht dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
nades relbmaR dlo eht fo snoitom eht ot demotsucca emaceb ydob reH
,ti fo edisni bmilc
?yzarc uoY“  .derepsihw eH
.ecaf elap a htiw sdneirf sih ot revo dekool eH
.dednopser ehS ”!efil ym fo gnihtemos ekam yllanif nac I
.oga sruoh wef a ereh ’nittis uoy dettops enim fo ydduB
,rehtorb reh ot dednetta ehs sA
.rehtorb reh ot troper ot eton fo gnihton saw ereht ,won roF
.meht fo owt eht rof egufer efas on saw erehT
hself fo sknuhc llams htiw semit wef a mih ta epiws ot deunitnoc ehS
.gnisselb a gnieb srewop dnuof wen reh tuoba ,sdrow s’avreiM no detcelfer azilE
ssem gnibbos a tfel saw rekcatta reh ,enod dna dias lla nehW
.noitcerid reh sdrawot stohs wef a ffo pop ot deganam namnug eht erofeb dnuorg eht ot netaeb teg rehtorb reh draeh ehS
.erofeb morf serutaerc eht eb ot ti demussa azilE
.ekops dna sthguoht reh derehtag avreniM
.dnik ni guh eht denruter retal eh
redael kcap eht ta noisserpxe desufnoc a dehsalf azilE
,dnah ta yrots eht ni
,ecnelis daed fo sdnoces wef a retfA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”!ti ekil attog I naem t’nseod sroodtuo gnipeels ot desu er’uoy esuac tsuJ
dnah s’retsis sih deppat maharbA
,revewoh ,devil trohs saw noitarbelec ehT
,flesym rof gnivil ton fo derit m’I
?kcab egnahc nac I yaw a ereht sI“
aedi eht detsetorp ton dah serutaerc eht
fo tuO .ffirehs lacol eht otni uoy nrut ot evah annog m’I ,won tuB
.reh ta kcab decnalg avreniM dna
,sivaD suiraD yb ”tfiG ehT“
!evila er’uoy ,eb esiarP“
.elzzum sti derewol dna
,reh no skcirt gniyalp dnim deniard doolb reh saw siht derugif ehS
.yek eht nrut yllacitnarf ot deunitnoc maharbA ”…tsuJ
.maharbA detnorfnoc nem eht sa nades eht fo edis eht tsniaga detser dna
,emit tsal eno reh ecarbme ylthgit ot esolc ni denael eH
.erugif wen eht ezilitu ylluf ot drawkwa ylthgils ti edam
tuo ekam dluoc eh llA
.deneppah tsuj dah tahw fo noitalpmetnoc rehtruf nopu
.kaeps ot retsis sih ediseb tog ylkciuq dna
.snaelrO weN ot pirt rieht gnirud noitcerid s’rehtorb reh raen ecnalg ot ton deirt ehs
.seert yb detcurtsbo yliramirp saw ti tub
.desaercni yltnacifingis dah deeps reh taht dnuof dna meht cimim ot detpmetta azilE
.og tel nehT“  .dedaelp ehS
ylthgit rood eht demmals ehS
.dnim ruoy egnahc uoy fi yats ot dnuob ton era uoy hguohT
thgilnoom fo ecnalbmes oN
.nem rehto eht tsap teg ot dah ehs
kram sti dnuof dah tohs dnoces ehT
.tnemevap gnivom eht otno mih dessot dna tuo mih deggard ehs sa
.epahs railimaf sti otni demrofer enips reh
kcap eht morf yawa ekorb sevlowerew eht fo eno erofeb gnol t’nsaw tI
.revo nrut t’ndluow enigne eht tub
.nugtohs eht dedaol yletarepsed eh sa rehtorb reh dniheb dedleihs taeskcab eht ni hctiM dettops ehS
.selohtop dna skcarc egral ssorca deddiks ti sa
a sa ti yfissalc lliw ffirehS
.meht esaeppa ot sepoh
.em rof enod ev’uoy gnihtyreve etaicerppa I
,egar eht ,raef eht ,niap ehT
dnim reh ni gnar noitseuq tahT
,kcap reh ot kcab denrut avreniM sa tsuJ
.erised uoy fi flowerew eht fo syaw eht uoy hcaet dna
”?ti toG .enif eb ll’uoy
,reh gnihcaorppa saw gnihtemos draeh ehs nehW
revo dehcaer sdnah reh
!ris ,uoy knaht oN“
!tfel ew erofeb oot meht dlot I ekil ediug levart detadpu taht teg t’ndid enoemos retfa yap ot ecirp llams a s’tI“
ecneirepxe ot detnaw reh fo edis rehtona ,teY
,pu dekool azilE nehW
slaem rieht eta owt ehT
.reh ot ekops eciov eninimef raelc a
deb reporp a ni peels ll’ew ,thginot retfA
.gnieb wen a otni detfihsepahs ehs sa
,maharbA .namow nwo ym eb em tel ot
.niaga dias ehS ”!oG“
thgit a ni deldduh eh sa
.ados fo elttob ssalg dellihc reh dna
.eromyna roiretxe reh dnuora parw t’ndluoc sdnah sih
ni uoy ekat nac eW“
.tlah a ot emoc ot kcurt eht rof hguone gnol no gnah ot elba saw ehS
.denialpxe azilE
.reh dnuora sthgis eht ni koot dna detsujda seye s’azilE  .tsaeb suoicoref a otni noitamrofsnart reh detelpmoc dah ehs
.thgin eht otni gniraeppasid erofeb daor eht otno llup ylwols dna
flesruoy evas ot esohc uoY
amuart lacisyhp eht morf tuo dessap t’ndah ehs
.raews I ,gnol siht ekat yllamron t’nseod tI“
.nem eht fo eno morf ekoms etteragic dna
.flowerew a otni tfihsepahs ot nageb dna
gnol deyalpsid dna kcab spil sti dellup dah tnorf yrev eht ta eno ehT
.seirots reh hguorht epacse ot ytinutroppo yreve koot ehs neht
.mih ot txen tas ehs sa reh otni raet tliug fo thgiew yvaeh a tlef azilE
.efink lavivrus egral a dleh dna
.mutnemom retsaf a niag ot drawrof tnirps ot sgel dna smra rieht dezilitu lla yehT
,ylthgils daeh reh dekcoc azilE  .hteet ralugna
.tegrat tsrif eht saw dna
noitasrevnoc eht draehrevo maharbA
.maharbA dna reh rof noitulos efas suoivbo on saw ereht
.ssenkrad eht ni swodahs yzah tuo ekam ylno dluoc yeht
.esnopser sih ta daeh reh koohs ylpmis avreniM
.snoitseuq erom neve htiw mirb eht ot dellif dnim s'azilE ,deneppah dah revetahW
.seye sih ni dehsalf egar fo stnih sa
sbmil gniworg reh ot yaw evag triks dna esuolb reh fo cirbaf ehT
.deifiralc avreniM ”,enola sruoy dna
.deyalpsid ylprahs hteet eninac sti htiw meht no deniag ylwols taht wodahs krad a saw
!su rof hcum os enod ev’yeht tuB“
ediskcab reh tsniaga derettahs dah
.thgil tesnus eht rednu koob reh daer ot detpmetta dna
.erif no erew eh hguoht sa deliaw dah revird eht yhw ot sa desufnoc saw azilE
.koob ydnah a dna
,shtaerb rieht dleh yehT
.tsrif reh ot teg t’nod srettirc eht fi
,evitcepsrep reh morF
.kaeps ot deraperp saw ti hguoht sa
?meht dnuora luos yrev ym yrub ot ekil s’ti tahw wonk uoy oD
.reh dniheb laedro elohw siht tup ylpmis dna
yaw a hcus ni demrof
,rehtruf rednuop dluoc ehs erofeB
;derrulb noisiv reH
.efil ot deraor yllanif enigne eht
.htiw nigeb ot ecnaraeppa yltsaeb eht no denwad reven ehs hguoht sa dekan meht erofeb doots namow erutam a
,em tsurt ot uoy rof si gniksa m’I llA
kcap reh fo tser eht fo snoitcaer eht degduj neht ehS
.edis tfel reh no trid pu dekcik dah dna dessim stohs eht fo enO
,em htiw gniugra fo daetsnI
,ega rieht dnuora eb ot deraeppa eh
,gnivael ton era lla’y sa gniees ,thgirlA“
”.lleh ekil nur dna tserof eht rof ekam ot uoy tnaw I
.meht sserdda ot drawrof deppets azilE
kcurt sih ot denrut nam eht
.lamron t’nsi ereht tuo s’revetahw
”?thgir ,strap eseht dnuora retiol ot lagelli s’ti ,wonk uoY
.yliraropmet meht dednilb dna
,rewsna dluoc ehs erofeB  .deksa eH
,stiucsib yrettub ylbmurc deird
,kcab decnalg ehs nehW .taoc ruf kcalb
suoladnacs fo selat tsuj naht erom deniatnoc skoob s’rekcaP
.ssarg llat eht otno nellaf ehs dna
,ydob reh tuohguorht sdaerps noitasnes gnilgnit rethgil A
.yob eht eitgoh dna epor eht teg og hctiM
.yltpmorp deilper redael eht dna
”.retsis ybab ym ,eb esiarp ,neht litnU
thgin eht tuohguorht ysub dnim reh peek ot thguos ehs ,teY
ssensuoicsnoc deniager rehtorb reh nehw hguohT
,ria eht ni gnuh sdrow reH
.maharbA desserdda dna
s’azilE tsniaga ecaf reh egdun yllausac ot ni denael ehS
sehtolc dedderhs fo sdnuos eht yb dewollof saw ti erofeb pleh rof seirc s’nam eht draeh enoyrevE
.llafthgin emaceb tesnus ecno flesreh tcartsid regnol on dluoc ehs hguohT
.pirt suoudra na hcus retfa
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
swalc fo noitamrof eht ni degnahc slianregnif reH
.mih no mrah yna tcilfni ton ot smra reh otni rehtorb redlo reh detsioh yltneg azilE .yrujni daeh suoires a dereffus eh hguoht sa revo dezalg erew seye sih
em ot esolc repus tog tI
,htaerb ekat ot elba saw maharbA elihW
,retpahc etirovaf reh fo dne eht deraen ehs erofeB
hcaorb ot mih rof tcejbus drawkwa na llits saw ti
rehtorb reh htiw daor eht no kcab daeh dluoc ehS
,erugif ekil eninac eht etipsed dnA
maharbA defrawd won dah
?yenruoj eritne rieht tuohguorht lufraef sa neeb evah yeht dluow
.tserof eht morf rac rieht otni gnireep seye gninihs fo riap a dettops dna denrut azilE
.elbareferp era nwonknu eht fo srorret thgin eht hcihw ot
,don ykahs a htiW  .deilper eH
.enot s’maharbA fo ytilitsoh neddus eht ta htaerb reh dleh azilE  .delley eH
.rehtorb ruoy dna
.efil eno siht evah ylno I
dnim reh raelc ot seye reh desolc azilE
.nemow rehto rof noitcartta nwo s’azilE fo noitarolpxe na dewolla tub
.tnemevom gniltsur fo sdnuos eht pu dekcip srae reh
”!ti gniyub er’uoy ,dnif ew noitats ossE txen ehT
.rac rieht morf tuo deppets ylwols neht owt eht
avreniM modeerf fo mucidom eht
.reh fo tuo dniw eht dekconk dna
.meht morf srumrum tfos raeh ot detrats ehs hguoht sa
.llams emaceb erutsop sih
.dednopser maharbA
.hteet ecreif sti deyalpsid erutaerc eht sa
.won ti ot tniop on s’ereht ,waN“  .deksa deT ”?reh teg og ew dluohS .elfir a yltcaxe t'nia gniht siht tub ,sgel eht rof gnimia saw I“  .dias revird ehT
.od ot dnetni I tahw yltcaxe s’taht dnA
”,’nivael yrruh a ni t’nera owt uoy smees ti tuB
.rekcaP niV morf seno yllaicepse
ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”,em htiw thgir tis t’nseoD
namuh a ekil dnats ot elba saw ehs
,edisni erom wef a erew erehT
,ylimaf dednetxe ruo htiw laed ot gnivah daerd woh dna
evom ot desufer ydob reH
efil tnalp eht ni dekrul erutaerc revetahW
,reh erofeb erutaerc eht fo ezag eht tem azilE  .dias eciov A ”!oG“
.uoy devas ohw seno eht t'nerew ew dna
.redael kcap eht morf emoc dah eciov eht hguoht sa
,revird eht rof sA
.niaga edisni dereep azilE
remmah egdels toh a hguoht sa saw tI
”tfiG ehT“   -si hcihw dnA
noitavlas fo ecruos elos rieht sa detca sthgildaeh ehT
!won ,evael ot deen eW“  .denway maharbA
.tseuqer eht nopu denediw seye s'avreniM  .deksa ehS
,gnola emoc dluow rehtorb reh dehsiw azilE sa hcum sA
”!tey ,reh llik ot desoppus t’nerew uoY !deT ,ti nmad doG“
!ti ees neve t’ndluoc I dna
.sselnoitom tnemevap eht tsniaga dial nam eht sa
.dehsinif avreniM
.seye yggab sih debbur eh erofeb
kcab decnalg ehs nehw ,flesreh ot setunim wef a retfa hguohT
dedlof smra reh tpek azilE
.ni daeh sih dereep revird ehT ”?kciuq laer rac ruoy leufer nac ew
.epahs devruc a no ekat ot nageb enips reh sa
.ytic eht ni kcab er’ew ekil toN
.delaeh yletelpmoc tub lla dah erofeb morf dnuow tohsnug ehT
.wodniw edis revird s’maharbA dehcaer eh erofeb stekcop htob edisni sdnah sih detser eH
thgilhsalf a htiw
;ereh ti ekil t’nod I
?ereh revo thgirla gnihtyrevE“
”!won ,rac eht fo tuo petS
”!gnihtemos yrt t’nseod eh erus ekaM
wef a tsal t’now ehS
”?kcap ruoy nioj dluoc I fi elbissop eb ti dluoW“
.emarf rood latem eht otni swalc reh deddebme dna nugtohs eht fo og tel azilE
.ystna emaceb dna
wodniw rac derewol flah eht hguorht ekorb smra yzzuf gnol reH
.noitnetta reh teg ot
.edih ruoy eucser ot srewop reh esu ot esohc ehs dnA
enot noitseuq ekil-namuh a ni tfig drow eht dias ylgnimees enO
.tserof eht edisni stops gnidih suoirav morf snoinapmoc owt thguorb dah meht deklats revetahw ,emit sihT
.mih dnuora elcric-imes a demrof oirt eht sa decnivnoc t’nerew sreppandik rieht
.ria daed eht llif ot slevon reh fo eno no pu hctac ot desu saw emit reh ,taht dnoyeB
,rehtruf detsetorp deT erofeB  .dias revird ehT
.reh ecarbme ylthgit ot drawrof tpael eh
.ssenkrad fo aes eht gnoma
noisiv dnuofwen reh htiw
”!su ta ’nikool gnihtemos s’erehT
.tcepsorp eht ta mra reh otni deddebme slian reH
.swen neddus eht morf snoisserpxe elpitlum dehsalf ecaf s’maharbA
.eltsihw gnorts a tuo tel dna
.sgnieb hctirdle hcus rof elbissop saw hceeps namuh hguoht sa
reh edisni deltserw sgnileef detcilfnoc owT
!em eno evah ylno I tuB“
eht ni draobhsad eht no sdnah rieht decalp meht fo htob ehT
.repap xaw ni delaecnoc
,dekcol seye gnilkraps rieht fo htob htiW
.detapissid ylwols dnim reh ni noisnet eht tlef ehs
.niks sih otni deddebme ssalg nekorb fo sdrahs lareves eht morf doolb htiw deniar ecaf sih
.detadtuo neeb dah spots rieht fo ytirojam eht ,kooB neerG rieht fo noitidda tnecer eht yub ot togrof yldednimtnesba ehs esuaceB
?evivrus uoy did woH
thgilyad eht fo dlrow nwonk eht ni sgnihT
.dehsirep meht fo htob eht fi detatsaved eb dluow rehtom reh wenk ehs
”!rehtorb ym ot klat ot tnaw I
,rac eht morf tuo deppets owt eht erofeB
ecalp ni gnitfihs tpek kcurt eht edisni nem owt eht
”?ew era erehw dnA
.flesti enigne s’kcurt eht fo sdnuos eht eviecrep ot elba saw gnirrae evitisnes repyh reh ,meht neewteb ecnatsid eht etipseD
,dleihsdniw kcab eht no galf sraB dna sratS eht yb derucsbo erew serugif rieht tub
;tnelis enog dah maharbA  .detroter ehS
eip otatop teews fo ecils a dna
.elcihev rieht ot esolc emac ti nehw nwod dewols dah taht rac enol ddo eht saw erehT
reh ta deknilb ylwols tI
.ecaf s’azilE derehtoms ylraen taoc ruf kciht eht ;dnuorg eht ot reh dennip erugif yvaeh ehT
”,strap eseht ni efildliw ees ot dnuoB
tnemtrapmoc evolg eht ni koob acitore reh dehsad azilE .tah rueffuahc sih no decalp dna debbarg eh erofeb
thgim hcus htiw tuo demaercs ehS
noziroh eht revo noom lluf eht fo tnih eht deciton azilE
.pu trats enigne kcurt gnilbmur eht fo sdnuos eht draeh lla yeht
.su ta gnieye saw ti yaw eht ekil t’ndid tsuJ“
,rohtua god dliw nacirfa reeuq kcalb a
lufknaht eb dluohs uoY
,tnaem taht tahw derednop azilE erofeB
.tserof eht sdrawot detnirps dna
kcurt eht morf gnitixe trihs dialp der a ni nam etihw a dettops owt ehT
!su gnisahc s’gnihtemoS“
deworruf sworbeye s’rehtorb reh taht eciton ot detrats azilE ,revewoH
tfig ruo uoy evag ylpmis tsuj eW
.koob suoladnacs a hcus htiw reh dettops eh fi
ylrobhgien laer eb ot ’niyrt saw I ,wonk uoY“
,weiv resolc a rof ni emac revird eht nehW
.meht no denwad ti gnittel owt eht
.eno hcae kcol ot devom dna
.esnopser a hcus detcepxe yeht hguoht sa
.ffo deps dna daor enilniam eht otno evird ot detrats erofeb morf kcurt ehT
,mih ot teg dluoc ehs erofeB
.egar a otni azilE tnes dah
”,sevlowerew otni meht nrut ylno lliw os gnioD
spil sih depacse nway duol A .rac sih dekrap dna daor eht fo edis eht otno ffo dellup yllautneve maharbA
?em sekat ti erehw ees dna
etats larutan derreferp reh otni kcab flesreh demrofsnart avreniM
”!dniheb uoy evael t’nac I ,sulP
.egakcerw eht morf flesmih eerf ot deirt dna tleb taes sih htiw deltserw eH
.meht htiw pu dehctac yllanif dah erofeb morf serutaerc eerht eht
,ffo tuhs sthgildaeh eht htiW
.rehtorb reh denekawa dah nades eht edisni noitommoc ehT
.trid eht otno nwod mih dial dna
kcab denrut revird ehT