”!ti no sdneped tsevrah doog sraey txeN
.devirra gnirps erofeb tey emit gnol a eb dluow ti dna retniw saw retniw saw retniW
”.pu uoy kcab tsuj d’I derugif adnik I oS“
.nehw kcab yaw tenretni eht derevocsid ehs nehw
,yltfos dias dna delims ytitcenacS
.tsetorp s’roinuJ gninword dna ylduol gniyalp
retcarahc reh otni nrob saw yyxiV
,hguone tsuj daeh reh gniwob dna
gniklaw deppots ehs
,lavitseF ’wonS tsriF‘ eht saw noisacco ehT
.alleB yb daeh sih fo kcab eht ot pals a deviecer eh siht gniyas retfA
,deyalp dnab eht sA
.samohT dehgual ”,I dluow sA“
.nopu delpmart dna daeh reh morf dekconk saw nworc s’airotciV
,gniyalp deppots eoJ yelruC
,ylderutan doog ,erihsnehtorF taC ot dias ytitcenacS knukS .deklaw yeht sa swap dleh dna
.ereht saw egalliv eht morf enoyreve tsomlA
.noom eht fo lluf eht yb detanimulli saw hcihw
”,enoD“ .ni demihc alleB
,seirots reh ekil uoy fI
.ecnatculer s’roinuJ ta derednow tneserp enoyreve taht
,tnaidar yletulosba dekool airotciV
…mra ni mra gniklaw ot swap gnidloh morf tnew yeht ,drow a tuohtiW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,ria llihc eht ni duolc a edam eciov siH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.gnidnats neeb d’llah ecnad eht gnol sa yltcaxe
emaceb neht llah ecnad ehT
daeh s’knukS gnuoy eht nopu telcric llams eht decalp mussoP dlo ehT
,royaM eht ot ylthgil deppets airotciV
.tsehc gib sih ot depparts draob hsaw eht no ztlaw eht rof mhtyhr eht tuo deppat eh
.esac yna ni emoh yaw eht no pots tsrif eht si hcihw
ssik lausnes …tfos
tnelis yletelpmoc
.neppah ot nwonk neeb dah tI
,yllive delims airotciV
neeuQ sih ot drawrof evom ot nrut sih won saw tI
”.thgin siht ylimaf ym htiw yats ylimaf ruoy taht tseggus lliw I ,rehtaew tnemelcni eht ot euD
”.krow nwo ym deliops evah dluow I ylekil toN
,nway eguh a denway raeB ehT
.pu naelc eht rof gninrom gniwollof eht kcab emoc lla dluow klof nemow eht taht dna
.dnuorg tsol yldipar eh ,ti tsniaga delggurts eh hguoht dna
,ylnepo mih ta gnilims saw knukS airotciV
;dlo snoitareneg net saw noitarbelec eht
.drawrof dehsup gnieb flesmih dnuof knukS gnuoy eht ,niaga ecnO
.gniyalp deppots dna dehgis eoJ yelruC
”?raed ew t’ndluow ,dethgiled eb dluow eW“
.slwahs neloow ni pu depparw ylivaeh erew htoB
seirreb yloh eht fo der ehT .yltcefrep
,’ztlaW wonS tsriF ehT‘ gninnigeb
”!neeuQ sih yb dessik eb llahs gniK deralced eht dna htrof thguorb eb ti teL ?eoteltsim eht si erehw …enoynA“
,noitarbelec tsrif eht dleh ohw erus etiuq saw eno oN
.taC ycuL ta kool did ehs emit siht dna
.egalliv llams rieht fo royaM eht yb detneserp sa ytlayor fo kram reh saw sihT
,ylduol dias ehs ”,eoteltsiM“
.dedda remraf dlo eht
,wons hserf eht fo ffo gnitcelfer thgilnoom eht nI
?airotciV neeuQ riaf eht htiw ecnad t’nac uoy taht eralced os uoy taht nosaer eht si tahw
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,deklaw ycuL dna roinuJ sA
ruf kcalb reh fo enihs eht detnecca taht sserd etihw wons a ni desserd gnivah
tlef dna thguoht ehs tahw ,siht ekil emit a ta taht gniwonk
,ytitcenacS ta dekool lla yehT
”,sukcur eht ni yldab oot od t’ndid seviw ruo taht deciton osla I .did ti tahT“
;nway suomrone na evag
”ztlaW wonS tsriF ehT“ saw sihT
,drawrof emac knukS airotciV
”,gnihtemos od ot dah I“
.xofyyxiv :si etisbew reh
noitelpmoc sti tA .elpuoc a sa
”.hctam tnaem I wonk lla uoy …hctam tnaem I ?gnilpuoc yas tsuj I diD“
.seirreb ylloh fo snworc rieht gniraew meht fo htob dna
.mih ot ylteiuq derepsihw ehs ,drawrof gninaeL
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rae sih ta debbur dna niaga delggig eH
.meht rof tuo gniyalp amardolem eht gniyojne ylevitcelloc erew sregalliv ehT
.yhs ylrevo gnieb tsuj saw eh thguoht tsom dna
,dias eh ”,delkcit tahT“
.eciov tseixes reh ni ylduol decnuonna ehs
.nem eht dniheb tsuj dewollof anilataC dna ehS
.rae sih ni derepsihw eh ,revo royaM eht gnilangiS
.mih fo tnorf ni nwod tlenk ylerumed
;htaerb evitcelloc rieht dleh won sregalliv ehT
”,enilced t’nac uoY“
,emoh klaw eht nO
rethgual duol fo hsar a saw erehT
noiton dootsrednu ylraelc dna deliev elttil
.etius dewollof dnab sih dna
”ztlaW wonS tsriF ehT“
.regna ni seye reh detniuqs
emos edam yllautca dah rehtom reH
.ylderutan doog ,dias samohT
niaga draob hsaw sih no yawa gnippat nageb eoM yelruC
,eip otatop teews a fo noissessop ni flesreh dnuof ,nrut ni ,ehS
”.seviw rehto eht ot gnignoleb ynam doog a kcuhc uoy ees did I tuB“
.egats llams eht fo ffo llaf ot gniog saw eh fi sa ylthgils dereggats dna
.ylhsival dewob dna
.seirreb yloh fo nworc llams eht detpecca
.teiuq emaceb sgniht niaga ecno dna redael rieht dewollof dnab siH
,wap s’efiw sih gnikat ,dias samohT
.lwob naeb eht ni wap ruoy was I eveileb I“
”,sacarf eht detrats yllautca ohw nees eb ot sniamer
.yaw eht fo tuo tsuj pu dellup neht dna
.’neeuQ wonS‘ s’raey siht yllaiciffo won saw ehS
.niaga draob hsaw sih no yawa gnippat nageb eoM yelruC
,ylderutan doog enilef eht deilper
.stug eip yrrebeulb htiw derevoc llits saw ,roolf eht no yats ot hguone yvvas ,roinuJ
,neeuQ wonS a saw ereht taht won
.ylippah kcab dellac royaM eht
,etius dewollof dnab siH
.suoivbo oot ylno saw gnirap eht os
swap ynam yb drawrof dehsup gnieb flesmih dnuof roinuJ
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.eno yb eno pots a ot gnimoc ,dewollof dnab siH
yb os saw siht dlot neeb dah eH
.deriuqer saw gniK wonS a
,reh dlot ytitcenacS ”,esac taht nI“
;knukS roinuJ emit tsal eno uoy ksa lliw I“
.ecaf eht ni erauqs reh thguac seotatop dehsam fo bolg taerg a nehw
”.evah dluow ylniatrec I
,royaM eht fo pleh eht htiw ,airotciV
a( deneppah dah tahw ssucsid ot llah nwot eht ta teem rub
.xoF yyxiV yb ztlaW wonS tsriF ehT“
.thguoht siht yb deticxe saw ehs dna ,now dah ehS
.daeh sih nopu nworc ralimis a ecalp dluoc ehs os
”,airotciV taht fo dalg ylniatrec m’I“
.eciohc elos s’neeuQ eht saw sihT
eugnot reh dleh ehs tub ,’!enim
.devirra retniw fo wons tsrif eht retfa keew eno yltcaxe raey yreve dleh
”?etteknukS elttil raed
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ecaf sih otni ti dehsup yltpmorp dna
”.seotatop dehsam sa llew sa etiuq worht t’nod yeht tub ,lwob naeb eht ni ydaerla saw wap yM
.was I seY“ .delkcuhc eH
.’ztlaW wonS tsriF ehT‘
,remmus gnidecerp eht devlovni yllacitnamor neeb dah riap ehT
.rellet yrots nrob larutan a tub
,niaga draob hsaw sih no yawa gnippat nageb eoM yelruC ”…tuB“
pleh ot redro ni sredlE egalliV eht fo hcae debirb gnivah
.revo ekat dluow rellaC ecnad erauqS a dna ffo riap neht dluow tneserp enoyreve
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.noisacco siht rof tsuj emitdeb retniw sih dnoyeb llew pu deyats gnivah
.deit neeb dah ti hcihw nopu kcits eht morf nwod gnilgnad tuo thguorb saw eoteltsim fo girps A
,roinuJ ot txen gnidnats taC lrig elttil eht ,nosrep tahT
redluohs s’taC eht no wap a tup alleB ”.oot dah tsuj I …llew
,emit emas eht ta emoc ot erew srettirc elam ehT
,tneserp enoyreve morf psag evitcelloc a saw erehT
”,gniK ym sa knukS roinuJ esoohc I“
,ecilA ta dekniw eH
kcab doots neht dna
.stcejbus wen reh gnoma deklaw ylwols airotciV sa
.seip deniur esoht fo wef doog a dekab I“
ynapmoc reh ni eerht rehto eht desuac ,esruoc fo sihT
.meht fo tser eht naht os erom hcum dna
,ecnad eht retfa uoy rof snalp sah ehs erus ma I
.gniyalp deppots dna dehgis eoJ yelruC
”,deirram ton m’I …oN“
.hpmuirt fo kool reh gnirevoc on saw erehT
.noitapicitna ni spil reh gnikcil dna stsaerb llams reh gnibbur ereht gnidnats reh was dnim s’htuoy roop eht ,mih ot tuo dleh smra reh htiw doots ylno ehs hguoht dna
”?deirram er’uoy gniyas uoy erA“
.elohw a sa egalliv eht ot elttil derettam
”.roinuJ ruoy dna ,ycuL ruo fo ekas eht rof tbed rieht ni yltaerg ma I ,saw ti reve ohW“
.rewsna sih rof detiaw enoyreve sa
.elgnis etiuq saw roinuJ wenk tneserp enoyreve ecnis
llits tI“ .mih dlot ehs ”,esnefed fleS“
,nar noitidart sA
.eciov duol yllauqe na ni royaM eht deksa
;derettalps doof ylraelc saw ecaf reh
ym niaga taht saw tahw …neht woN
.evitsef yletulosba dekool nworc reh ni sevael eht fo neerg eht dna
,dessarrabme ylsuoivbo saw eH
.nesohc erew yeht nehw gniK gnieb morf enoemos tneverp ylbissop dluoc taht gniht ylno eht saw sihT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
;wonS tsriF eht fo neeuQ eht rof doof lauxes eb ot saw eH
…flesruoy rof kaepS“
.neeuQ eht ssik dna drawrof emoc won ot evah uoy syas noitidarT“
.dluoc eh sa duol sa tuo delley eh ”!t’nac I“
.enitneprut ekil tib a gnitsat gnihtemos htiw ti dekips dah
.knukS roinuJ ot tnew seye lla
.’ztlaW wonS tsriF ehT‘ yalp ot gninnigeb niaga ecno
”!airotciV neeuQ liah llA“   xoF yyxiV yb
.swap gnihsup eht fo lla morf yawa teg ot tpmetta na ni roolf eht ot gnippolf
,evael tsum enoyreve taht eerced eht yb derotser ylno saw redro ,dne eht nI
.sredluohs reh fo gurhs a htiw og eno taht tel alleB
,t’ndah uoy fI“ ,reh dlot dna
,ylduol decnuonna eh
”?ti t’ndid worht yssem a rof edam tahT
.noitseuq eht ot deilper eh
.gnihtyna dias ton dah ohw
.ti htiw tsehc eht ni erauqs ,neeuQ wonS remrof dna ,efiw sih tih dna gongge sih fo tfel saw tahw gnulf
,ynam fo thgiled eht ot ,yltnerappa enoemos dna
.emit erom eno pu derif dnab sih dna
,rof gnikool saw ehs ohw gnidniF
.snoitceffa s’knukS roinuJ kcab niw ot emehcs s’rethguad reh htiw
.ecnatsid etercsid a ta dewollof stnerap rieht elihw daeha deklaw taC ycuL dna knukS roinuJ
…roinuJ ruoy htiw nettims os si ycuL roop yM“ .deilper ehs
s’eH‘ ,tuo lley ot detnaw ehS
.eciton ot demees moor eht ni nosrep rehto eno ylno hguoht
,noisacco eht rof gnos deriuqer eht deyalp dnaB guJ suoicadoB s’eoM yelruC sa ,sdnoces nihtiW
” …gnilpuoc retteb a fo kniht tonnac eno rof I dna
.teiuq ylegnarts deniamer taC anilataC
.egalliv eht fo yrotsih dedrocer eht ni thgif doof tsegral eht derrucco ereht
.noitcerid yreve morf gniylf doof saw ereht neht dna
.’ztlaW wonS tsriF‘
.deralced royaM eht ”!aedi didnelps A“
”.was I egabbac delkcip eht htiw ydnah ytterp
.yltfos dias ehs ”,snworc eht elots ycuL“
,gongge eht otni neeb d’eH
--------------- .)hgual doog a evah dluow yeht dna
,niaga delley eh ”!t’nac I“
.ekoj eht fo tnemyojne eht ni sbir gniynapmocca dnuof swoble ynam dna ,gnihgual hcum saw erehT
.dias tsuj dah eh tahw hctac ot gnimees ,desuap eH
.tnemeerga yddig ni deddon mussoP dlo ehT
”,roinuJ uoy evigrof I“
.ylduol dias roinuJ ”!enilced I“ .won
.ecnetsixe yraerd esiwrehto na nevil did ti tub
.ylgninoitseuq reh ta kool ot
.eerf si gnidaer eht erehw moc.xofyyxiv
.deman eb ot deyarp meht fo lla dna sdneirf sih
…eguh a htiw tsetorp sih llits ot tuoba saw dna daeh sih debbarg ehS ”…tuB“
eht pu kcurts dnaB gnirtS dna guJ suoicadoB s’eoM yelruC
lufituaeb yletulosba os gnikool dna debmoc yltcefrep liat reh
,seotatop dehsam fo eguled eht gnikcud tsrif ta ,royaM ehT
.gongge sih fo knird rehtona koot dna delggig eH ”…gnilpuoC“
gnignis stnerap rieht fo seciov eht draeh yeht
,sregnif delbmiht sih htiW
;noitanoroc siht erusni ot stnemegnarra ’laiceps‘
.esohc uoy knukS gnuoy siht fo suolaej deedni ma I dnA“
evolg a devomer meht fo htob
”,espalloc ot tuoba si dnab ruo taht tcaf eht ot euD“
.derepsihw knukS elttil ytterp eht
,hgual a htiw deilper eh
.dnabsuh reh dlot ehs ”,knukS flesruoy rof ylno dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,xoF yyxiV yb
noitapicitna htiw zzuba ylkciuq saw moor eht dna edam saw kcip siht retfa derrucco gnitam a ynaM
”,efiw enif ym ,eurt si sihT“
…thgin siht tisiv a esuoh ruo gniyap eb lliw neeuQ wonS ’wen‘ eht taht sseug a erutnev dluow I“
”,riS dlO flesruoy od uoy sA“
,roolf eht nopu tas eh erehw ecaf s’roinuJ fo tnorf ni yltcerid decalp saw tI
,redluohs sih no daeh reh htiw ehs
,dloc eht fo sseldrageR
litnu pu ’lavitseF wonS tsriF“ yreve fo yaw eht neeb dah ,tsael ta ,tahT
.eciohc reh ta detniop ylwols dna
.eoteltsim saw ereht fi reh ssik ot dah roinuJ
,retirw thguat- fles a si ehS
ecnad tnatropmi tsom siht ecnad neht dluow yehT
,etius dewollof dnab sih dna
,raeB nworB eguh a ,eoJ yelruC
.neeuQ deman saw ehs sa teiuq yletelpmoc neeb dah ti dna ,llah ecnad egalliv eht ni erew yehT
guj a gnirb dluohs lla taht
;yhtorF ereht mra thgir doog a tog aY“
.mih ta delims anilataC
”?ti t’nsaw airotciV neeuQ ta seotatop dehsam eht werht taht uoy saw tI“
”,pu naelc a dna ,eip ,eeffoC“
.tahw wenk ohw neht dna
,kcab derepsihw eh