?gnineve siht em htiw enid ot uoy tpmet I
.thgin eht si thginoT
.nosrep thgir eht htiw
su dnimer selkcirp gohegdeh esohw ,esum cimoc eht ,ailahT gnilims ot dna ,sseddog reed eht
.nos egats sih ta gniraor morf gnitnap dna esraoh s’eH
.tar a ekil yug elttil a htiw yaw gnol a seog eniw deximnU
.ylimaf rieht fo yhtrownu dna nrob-wol s’ehs ton ro rehtehw
.sraE giB syas ”!taht ekil dehtorteb ruoy ot kaeps t’noD“  .os erom ton fi
,ailahT ot raews
tuB	:NOS EHT .ylsuoicipsus ,ecneidua eht ta tuo skool NOKILIHP
si dlo er’uoy nehw xes fo kniht oT .yob htiw reven
I	:SAMELOTP ?siht si tahw dnA	:SIKKA  .ydemoc a
?seot ym dnuor delruc liat ym dna wap ym ni nihc ym htiw ylevisnep gnittiS
ruoy no llits er’uoy ,si  gniht ’enam‘
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.sevals gninnuc rieht dna nem dlo ypmurg rof ton ,htuoy nedlog rof si evoL .si ti
,diap-llew ton er’eW
.ecnalab sih teg ot rallip eht no snael wap deyalps siH .yawa hsup elttil a mih sevig sotpeL .tacelop eht sdrawot syaws eH  ”…detnaw tsuj I
!deb fo tuo llaf yeht sa ylisae sa evol ni llaf yehT
.rats ym s’eH .nirg I
.mih ot gniklat detrats dah sgorf fo surohc a fi sa
.sraE giB rof dna mih rof...eraperp
nehT	:REHTAF EHT !esruoc fO	:ESUOM EHT  .esruoc fo
,niorg sih fo tnorf ni ti gnidloh si dna daerb fo faol a fo dloh tog s’eH
.gniltsirb si ruf siH
a erom ,gnilwoh dna sedis ruoy gnidloh uoy sah taht ynnuf fo dnik eht t’nsi yalp ruo
,tsac eht fo desingocer tsom eht s’eH
gnidnatsrednusim dna esiugsid s’erehT
.eraperp I elihw ereht yats mih tel ,eniF
.ertaeht si taht
.slasrever oN
]EDISA[	:NOKILIHP  .ega reh htiw desaercni ylno evah skool reH .ytuaeb a
”.wonk uoY .gnitca eht lla retfA .selcsum ym roF
.su ediseb srettahs ailahT .dnuorg eht ot ,yaw eht fo tuo sotpeL hsup I
.eruS“  .ynnuf yreV
llA	:NOKILIHP !htob su emusnoc lliw ti raef I ,egral os emoceb si tI
,lrig htiw evol ni sllaf yoB
:enecs txen eht rof emutsoc sih no gniworht s’ohw ,sraE giB ta ecnalg tnacifingis a htiw yawa sgnirps eH
yalP	:SAMELOTP ?knird a...	:SIKKA ...htiw trats nac ti ebyam tuB
,re ,na htiw em gnitsissa saw
pu daeh ym gard I tub ,troffe sekat tI
;samelotP fo esac eht ni ,sraey—
…wap a stfil sotpeL .ksa I
ehT…fo elat ruo ta ,su htiw hgual dna yrC !evals yliw eht
,nokilihP !nokilihP ,nokilihP
.ssenilevol fo noisiv
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.lrig a sa desserd nam eht syaS“
ehT	:NOKILIHP  .rehtaf ym taefed tonnac I dna nworg tey ton si enam
skeew rof elpoep eseht htiw gnikrow dna gnivil neeb ev’I
...eraperp em dah sotpeL cincip eht ot snoitubirtnoc siH .yrrow sih ni deppord s’eh
ll’tI	:SIKKA ?efil laer s’ti spahreP .yalp rytas a rO
”!haey hO“  .sotpeL ksa I
,drawkwa erom eil eht ekam ot tsuj ,dnA
,rehtaf tcirts eht teeM
htaerb ym hctac ot ecnahc a teg I os ,enecs gninepo eht ni ton m’I .tnap
.wohs etavirp nwo ruo ni gnirrats eb ll’ew noos dnA
,etib-dim desirpruS
thginot tub ,lasraeher ni niaga emit dna emit hceeps sih draeh ev’I
.ylsuoixna ti hctaw srotca ehT .selbbow tes ehT
pu kool lla eW  .selbbow tI
semit sseltnuoc rehto hcae etisoppo deyalp ev’ew
,noitcudes rof tuo m’I emit siht tuB
.mih sllet sotpeL ”,ytrap etavirp a si sihT“
.nem dlo ypmurg deyalp I erofeb
,em saw taht esuaceb wonk I
,hO	:NOS EHT .noitidnoc eno
,hA	:ESUOM EHT .sretne ESUOM EHT
!kcab yrruH
.epacse t’nac I dna llaw eht ot s’kcab ym os dnuora seldis xnyl eht tub
,llew - rehtom nwo reh si ydal eht skniht eH !pleH
,erutaerc teews a hcuS
,rE	:NOKILIHP ?rehtaf ym htiw kaeps lliw uoY
.seunitnoc tacelop eht
.sllaf yllanif dna ,dnuos gniparcs a htiw esab sti no skcor ,sreteet
pu sdne enoyreve erus ekam dna
”.doog yllaer erew uoy thguoht I“ …emos dnA
,drawer ym eviecer lliw I
.ti fo ycamitni eht ta llirht I dna
]mih seerf eh sa ,REHTAF EHT
,esnepsus dna kaerbtraeh
.retal ,retaL …eldnah
.dnuora nwolc sraE giB gnihctaw mih tops dna
,ecaf noil revo ksam noiL ”.samelotP“  .nokilihP
.taht wonk ot hsiw ton did I
”!sotpeL ,esruoc fO“
,ikahK yb dna ,xnyl kcurtsrats eht sa foohnorI mok’aT ,sraE giB sa
.sgniw eht otni egats eht morf nur dna ,evaw ,wob I
taem decips dna eseehc fo slecrap era tar eht dnuora derettacS
doof emos barg ,tsap teg ot tnaw I .ervueonam eW
.yuqolilos sih gnireviled si samelotP ,ereht tuO .sllab eht evah t’nod su fo tser ehT
ecin kool ot ti tnaw t’nod I naem t’nseod ffo ylsselerac deppir cinut ym evah ot gnipoh m’I esuaceb tsuj—
ydemoc fo terces eht swonk eh esuaceb
.modnaf yrruf eht fo tuo dna ni seirots trohs fo retirw dna
,ereh s’eH .dnim t’nod I tuB
.mih rof skrow ti dna ,gnimrofrep ton s’eh nehw retcarahc ni yats ,seod dna ,nac eh
.sgniht doog eht gnoma yldrawkwa gnidnats m’I os ,esop a no gnidiced llits m’I elihw sevirra sotpeL
.enO rednelS ehT
.evals yknuhc ,dega-elddim a gniyalp ot evals ynniks ,gnuoy a gniyalp morf enog ev’I ,eM
!nokilihP ,uoy knahT
.teews m’I kniht ot mih tnaw I esuaceb yenoH .ytlas
sedart lla fo flow a ,traH ydrA
”?ytrap eht ot drawrof gnikooL“
.detnaw I noitcaer eht etiuq t’nsi hcihW
.rehtaf ym revo yaws on dloh sdog eht
htiw ti sllif sotpeL tub—
.nokilihP ,reh evol
toN	:NOS EHT  .evol ot uoy rof slrig rehto eb lliw erehT
”.naem I tahw wonk uoy fi ,erom dnA
stnaw eH !em stnaw eH
,ydaer m’I emit eht yb dna—
!elbissopmi eb dluohs ti
esaelP	:NOS EHT ?tpurretni thgim I fI	:NOKILIHP  .taht toN...	:NOS EHT
,senips elbram sti htiw
,ekac yenoh a naht reteews neve gnihtemos si
.elttil a deppils tub
.sotpeL…si sotpeL .hguoht ,sotpeL
I	:SAMELOTP  .dneirf ,htooms ylniatrec si hceeps ruoY	:SIKKA ?htooms os ti si
yM	:NOS EHT .reh ni ti sah ehs won dnA
fO	:NOKILIHP ?nokilihP ,uoy t’nerew
,xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daeR
.uoY	:NOKILIHP .trad ym htiw reh deraeps I taht tluaf reh ton si ti ,lla retfA
eH	:REHTAF EHT ?ereh gniod evals ruoy si tahw...ot emoc evah I
hO	:REHTAF EHT  ?rehtegot eb nac ew taht won ees uoy oD
.esum cimoc ,ah aH .gnilims s’ehS
.egats no si ti yaw eht s’taht
,htrib elbon fo ma I ,ees nac uoy sA
,nos emosdnah sih
!ti ees og ,ton er’uoy fI
.retaerg gniworg dna
”.sotpeL ,shgual paehC
!rehtaf eht won dna nos eht tsriF
.reilrae no tup ynapmoc rehto eht ydegart dekaos-doolb eht retfa ,ffuts thgiL
yojne esaelP  .noinapmoc
,namow dlo na sa desiugsid rehtaf eht ot seog eh nehw
!sdog eht yB ]EDISA[ ?seod...ehS	:NOKILIHP
eH	:REHTAF EHT .rehtruf eriuqne ton llahs I	:ESUOM EHT  .rettam etamitni
?...ruoY	:NOKILIHP !nerdlihc ruo ssucsid ot
”sonokyM morf esuoM ehT“
yalp eht fo thgiew eht yrrac I dna samelotP—
,elbat a no gnidnats si sraE giB
”,taerg erew uoY“ *** .tixE
”.rats a er’uoY !uoy knaht ,sikkA ,hA“  .yffulf ylsuoegrog
renniw drawA rojaM asrU dna ltoyóC semit owt a ,reetyksuH yb
,elbaevol era uoy taht kniht elpoep dna revol a yalP
ecneidua eht morf rethgual fo elbrub a s’erehT
egdun emoS .sehtolc ym degnahc ev’I won ecnalg dnoces a em evig t’nod dworc eht fo emoS
”,ereht tuo ygrene fo toL“
,ythguaN !og ew erehT
t’noD	:SIKKA  .elbitpmetnoc dna ytrid
dluoC	:REHTAF EHT  !dnik oot era
.sotpeL ot syas eh
!sbuC	:NOKILIHP  .tixE !evol ruo fo yaw eht ni teg llahs gnihton dnA
.efil laer ni neppah taht ekam ot woN
.em tuoba s’ti enigami I .laer sleef ti
.rehtaf ruoy ecaf uoy pleh lliw I
”sonokyM morf esuoM ehT“
,hA	:NOS EHT .sretne NOS EHT
,oga sraey sdael citnamor yalp ot desu eh nehw rebmemer ohw snaf sah eH
.slaem wef a no pu hctac ot yaw doog a syawla si tsaef eht dna
.sgnidnatsrednusim cimoc oN
!eybdooG	:REHTAF EHT .tixE !eeh-eeT !gniht teews uoy ,thgir lla ,llew...tnaem I !hO	:ESUOM EHT
yM	 :NOS EHT ?noil a era uoy nehw ,god yrgna na ekil lworg uoy od yhw ,retsam
erehT	:SAMELOTP ***  .dworc deticxe eht hguorht em sdael eh dna ,syas eh
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.nalp eht saw taht
,pit eht ta tfut a rof tpecxe dnuob si
.recnad a ekil gniyaws
er’uoY	:SIKKA .seno ylgu eht rof toN
eht ot dnuor yaw ruo krow dna edis tuops eht ta trats ll’ew ebyaM
- yas ot gniyrt m’I tahW .sikkA ,sikkA	:SAMELOTP
.sevorppasid rehtaf sih tub
dnA	:NOKILIHP  .luos dna traeh ,eno siht evol I .em rof
”.si ti hguoht diputS .yalp eht no dnim ruoy peeK !kniht t’nod
.elggig dna repsihw dna rehto hcae
.rehtom reh yrram
.deednI	:NOKILIHP .sdog eht fo krow eht si ti spahreP
!eroda I mohw rehtaF gnilrad ,gnihtyna
.sdrow eht tuo ekam t’nac I hguohtla ,efil ertaeht eht tuoba seirots gnillet s’eh wonk I dna
”?ti did ,uoy fo tuo tol a koot ecnamrofreP“
?tiurf nettor worht spahrep
,gnorw seog ti nehw gniog peeK
.owt ym neewteb wap delbram eht psalc dna
s’teL	:SAMELOTP ?ffo emoc sksam eht nehw
stespu ohw dnal yawaraf a morf regnarts eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.lavorppasid fo slley dna ecivda detuohs
I	:REHTAF EHT  .deritta ylhcir tsom dna
hgual gnilbmur sih raeh nac I
”?sotpeL ot em ecudortni uoy naC“
.snaorg dna selkcuhc fo wolf ydaets
.sdne yalp eht woh wonk ll’uoy ,detacude er’uoy fI
I	:NOS EHT  .uoy rof dab sa tsuj ylbaborp dnA
,ylper I ”,hsikcep tsuJ“
nees evah I
?gnihtyreve xif ot evoba morf ni gnipoows sdog eht fo eno htiw sdne ti dna ,seilliw no-parts dna sekoj traf llA
uoY	:ESUOM EHT  .gnirpsffo ylevol ruoy fo taht sdeecxe ytuaeb ruoy
.snup elbirret dna swen gnitirw rof
.ehS	:NOKILIHP .yad hcae reriaf sworg ehs ,won dnA
,cinut sih gniggans ekil gniht elttil a yb dezaf eb ot noil eht ekil ton s’tI
.yalp eht fo trap lla s’ti gnikniht otni ecneidua eht loof
!sdneirF“  reetyksuH yb
,em depleh uoy evah syawlA
.seye nedlog s’samelotP otni kool dna
.tseuqer sih sreviled eh sa ,edis ot edis morf gniws neht
.yrotsih tsegnol eht htiw
.sdrawretfa noitarbelec a rof doom eht ni enoyreve teG
yllautca t’nsi eman ym taht ,semitemos ,tegrof I
stros nokilihP gninnuc dlo doog taht yas ot eciffuS
.esirprus ni esiar srae sih dna em ta ssorca secnalg samelotP
.reh retfa kool tsum
;ecneidua eht morf rethgual fo elbmur a s’erehT
erutaerc-flah tenretni ruoy ,anueL ,sotpeL sa
laog ruoy won
,nokilihP ,em dna
tcaf eht revo eltsirb I sa neve ,kniht I ,enim s’eH .etam ,ecnahc oN .sksa eh
.era lla eW .flesym llet I ,esnet s’eH
.epoh I ,ydegart a toN .wonk t’nod
,sehctiwt tnedor elttil
,hctiwt ot strats liat yM
.tsixe t’nod I fi sa edisa em gniredluohs ,sdnah knip htob ni ti sekat sraE giB dna…
t’noD	:SAMELOTP ...I	:SIKKA  .dekcip saw esuoM rof tsac eht ecnis reve sotpeL no seye yxof ruoy dah ev’uoy wonk I
,nelarD yb uoy rof daer ,reetyksuH yb
ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb dna
.egats eht no gnorw enog s’gnihtemoS  .tros rehto
nodotsaM no laicos.xobgod@reetyksuh@ ro
.lla retfa htrib elbon fo si ehs mih ecnivnoc ot
.rood eht skcik NOKILIHP
!rekrow tsaf a s’eh ,sdog eht yB
,dennuts skool sotpeL
,sedart lla fo flow a ,traH ydrA
,gnivael tsuj saw
,evitseggus dna yciuj dna epir ,sgif ekat I
,sserd etihw gnol a nI
”sonokyM morf esuoM ehT“ saw sihT
sdlof eht tsujda ot setunim wef a em sekat ti daeh ym revo sehtolc nwo ym pop I nehW
”?pu yrd uoy edam tahW“
emit hcum os dneps I dluow
,drawrof ylno ton s’tahT
?ti seod ,efil laer ni ylkciuq os emoc t’nseod tI	:SAMELOTP ?evoL	:SIKKA  .seY	:SAMELOTP ?eM	:SIKKA  .seY	:SAMELOTP  .hO .esuaP !oot deird
.gnorts si tnecs sih dna ,drah gnikrow morf toh si ydob sih
.ytterp skool ti os tuo gnihtyreve yal dna
.su ot pu syaws xnyl ehT
,ydob ehtil eht sa niaga gnol sa
.detacilpmoc si ydemoC
.nokilihP ,seiradnuob on swonk
,madam ,os yas yam I fI .ees od
,cinut ym sdnif wap sih dna htaerb sih no eniw s’erehT "...uoy naC“
rehtom s’esuoM eht eb ot gnidneterp
,ylduol oot ,yas I
,erutats llams sih gnitareggaxe
.redluohs ym no sdnal wap yvaeh s’samelotP
!uoy hceeseb I ,esaelp ,nokilihP O	:NOS EHT
.nrecnoc htiw tfos dna dnuor era taht seye tnedor otni pu ylevarb selims sotpeL
klaw tnedifnoc sih
dneirflrig sih yrram ot gniog s’eh taht ,noil eht samelotP yb deyalp
?nokilihP esuaP ?nokilihP
,lleW“  .tnemssarrabme dna truh ym edih ot ylpeed knird dna
.sekac yenoh gnilaets buc a saw I ecnis reve
oT[ !flesmih yb tuo dewolla eb t’ndluohs eH !loof dlo ylliS ]EDISA[	:NOKILIHP  .rood eht ni thguac emoceb sah ebor ym fo meh eht ,ees nac uoy sA
.taht ekil egats no pu yrd reven uoy dna
”.esle gnihtemos fo gnikniht saw I“
.ereh reh gnirb dna lrig ruoy ot oG
uoY	:SIKKA .esuac eht eb dluoc evol ylnO
.seiceps egats dna seiceps
!dehsinup eb llahs tI !rood ythguan
.evol sih fo htped eht stsetorp eh erom eht erom hgual ohw ,ecneidua eht rof reinnuf ti sekam taht dna
.niaga nrut ym s’tI
.krad eht ni ,terces ni sexaw tI
,seman retcarahc dna seman laer fo sdaerht eht ni delgnat teg llits I tub—
.eson sih sdloh dna cinut sih fo kcab eht stfil eh ,hctaw I sA
.rehtegot sthguoht ym teg dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,srellever eht fo tsom evoba gnirewot daeh eninoel sih ,samelotP
!gnihtyreve xif ot evoba morf nwod gnipoows ,esuM ym ,dog ym ,dog eht s’tI
.noitarbelec dna gnicnad dna gniknird neht dna ,yalp eht ,lavitsef ehT
,rehtaf sih gnillet s’eH
.reverof syats dna ,tlob gninthgil a sa yltfiws sa semoc evol ,egats
sraey rof uoy htiw detca ev’I
,nokilihP ,taerg si evol
.niaga flesmih eb lliw eh ytrap eht tA .noil gnuoy a ot
,yllaeR	:NOKILIHP .sretne nokilihP !noisiv a
?spil ym erofeb dleh gif a
,noitpeced dna yrekcirt
.snoitpeced gninnuc oN
tacelop morf mih gninrut
.ylleb lluf a ton
.htuom s’rehtona otni separg pop nac uoy esuaceb ,separg dna
.yvne htiw nrub I dna
!emit tuobA...re...I ,on ,rE	:REHTAF EHT ?retsam o ,em llac uoy diD	:NOKILIHP ESUOH EHT :ENECS ***
”.yalp eht deyojne uoy dalG .uoy knahT“
.htrae eht tih ti erehw daeh sih fo kcab eht gnibbur s’ohw ,tacelop eht gnilddarts m’I
.naf a tnaw t’ndid I
.tuoba ti gnilggaw
guj retaw eht barg I
!noeL fo esuoh eht fo rehtaf elbon tsom
!lavitsef reh ta etidorhpA sseddog eht ruonoh ot
.steliot cilbup eht ot og d’I ,taht ekil erutcip a ees ot detnaw I fI
.nos ruoy rof hctam enif a si rethguad ym taht uoy erussa ot emoc evah I
.egats eht ffo teg I dnoces eht sotpeL llet I
ro spih eninimef gniyaws htiw pu ti smah reven eH
,nerdlihc ruo fo erutuf eht ssucsid oT
.su fo htob no enil emas eht deirt s’eh taht
”.doog yllaer ,yllaeR“
.og em stel dna ylgnidnatsrednu sdon xnyl ehT  .specib
evah ot tuo er’yeht dna revo si pihsrow suoires ehT
,ydegart sa ylsuoires sa ti yalp ot si
,erutaerc-flah tenretni ruoy ,anueL
,dlohesuoh deredro rieht
thginot teem llahs
,trops rieht rof su gnihctaw yojne od yehT
.dworc s’thginot ni dellup s’taht eman sih s’tI
esuaP !tibbar eht sorE naht evol tuoba erom wonk dna
.tsehc ym revo snepo ti erehw ti gnidloh
.eniw fo stoL .eniw oslA
.debrab eb nac ydemoc taht
,citsanmyg dna gnisirprus emos ni gnigagne srytas htiw detaroced si ,eciton I ,guj eniw ehT
.diuqil ekil sevom ,dettops ,yknilS
,tsael tA	:SAMELOTP -gu ton
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf
!esruoc fo ,retsam gnuoy ,sey
.dnuora nam dlo eht nrut nac I tuB
,em ot txen stis eh nehW .syas eh
,esaelP .od
tsiser ot elba neeb sah reven nam dlo ehT
I	:NOS EHT  .dnuob eb ll’I ,llew sa strap rehto
!modeerf ym yub llahs I neht dna
”?thgir lla uoy erA“
.esuom a sa dna namow a sa mih ni eveileb uoY .tcefrep
.euc sih rof gnitiaw s’eH
si yrots s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.neddibrof erom dna
,liat yffulf sih dna
,etidorhpA fo eutats eht ot don I egats eht ot yaw ym nO
.yawynA	:ESUOM EHT .tixE !yaw eht yb ,emoclew er’uoY
”,doog yllaer erew uoy thguoht I“ !on ,on ,oN
tnetsixenon ym xelf I
.retsam ,esruoc
dnuof eb nac ”sonokyM morf esuoM ehT“
redwop wolley htiw debbur si taoc delppad lufituaeb sih ,won thgiR
,rae ym otni gnilbmum s’eH ”?edisa meht tup
,ecnahc lanif ym ,ecnahc yM
eW	:REHTAF EHT  .namow emas eht htiw evol ni era retsam gnuoy eht dna retsam dlo ehT
.krep tnedifnoc sti esol liat ym leef I dna
.taht wonk t’ndid...I	:NOS EHT  .eugnot ym
.rotarran eht sikkA sa
.drawrof oot s’taht ,oN ?ssarg eht no htgnel lluf denilceR
dna lufituaeb si sraE giB
”,knird a uoy teg s’teL“
.noitnetta fo erahs sih gnitteg si
rettiwT no reetyksuH@ wolloF
.ecnamrofrep eht rof pu deyeK
.su snioj sraE giB
dnA	:NOKILIHP !dedrawer ylhcir eb lliw uoY
.spohc ydemoc sih fo srerimda sa llew sa
elor eguh a ton s’tI
,dog dlohesuoh a erew I fi ,retsam
.sesicrexE .mU .sgniht
.gniws lluf ni ydaerla ytrap eht raeh nac I
”,enecs rehtom eht ni em gniucser rof sknahT“
.draeh ev’I os ro
keehc eht no kcep a tacelop eht sevig eH
.desraehernu si ti
,ecneidua eht morf selkcuhc era erehT .rae na kcoc I
evoL	:NOS EHT !ESUOM a si...EHS dnA
.redluohs ym no wap yvaeh a leef I ,yresim ym fo speed eht morF
.lla rof sgnidne yppah htiw ,pu depparw yltaen gnihtyrevE .tuo lla ti
,em ta kcab spans eh
.ni snael xnyl ehT
rotca…od dna og ot evah I ?yako ,retal em dniF
.skcol nrubua nwo sih htiw dexim warts fo elggarts a enam eht
.laog ym niw ot selcatsbo lla emocrevo ev’I ,oreh eurt a ekiL
.gnineve eht fo ecnamrofrep lanif eht erofeb
A	:REHTAF EHT ?tsal ta ti gnisol nam dlo eht sI ]EDISA[ ?retsam
?ti taht si ,ffuts dlo eht gniod eb rehtar d’uoY“
,llub eht sueZ naht lufrewop erom era uoy emoh ruo nI
ecnayonna artxe elttil a dnif ot eganam I ,tnemom eht liops ot pu nwohs s’eh degarne ylhguoroht m’I hguoht nevE
.evol fo stca ,elbissop yletinifed tub
,samelotP sa xofnogarD reppaD eht
,ydemoc a thginot uoy ot tneserp eW
dna ffo ksam ym llup I erehT
.rats reggib eht ot teg ot
!rehtom elbon s’devoleb ym tem evah uoy oS !rehtaF
*** !od esaelp ,esaelp
”?setad dna sevilo ,sgniht ykcans elttil esoht fo emos dna
.cinut ym morf trid gnihsurb ,yawa kcab I
”nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI“ ygolohtnA eht ni
sotpeL rof gninnacs m’I
sgniht sekil tacelop eht wonk I esuaceb sevilO
!lla ta nalp eht fo trap ton saw siht tuB
nO	:REHTAF EHT ?reh yrram ot gnisselb ruoy evah I od
nO	:SAMELOTP   .no hctac reven
.pu ti kcip t’now srae suomaf s’tar eht os eciov sih srewol dna em ot resolc selffuhs sotpeL
,ailahT gohegdeh ta dworc eht revo ecnalg I  .did I tuB
.mih ni ti dah eh kniht t’ndid I
gnuoY	:NOKILIHP  .pleh rof ,nokilihP ,uoy ot nrut I os dnA
rO	:SIKKA  .yrc ro hgual lliw esaelp ot epoh I ecneidua eht fi ton wonk I dnA
,gnirtswob a ekil tuat ydob mils
.hguone s’taht ,drol ym ,thgir
.ylimaf eht fo nos eht syalp ohw tacelop delbram eht
.enecs tsal eht fo tuo dna ni gninnur eht lla dna
ecnamrofrep a erofeb tae ot suovren oot syawla m’I—
?flesym egnarra I dluohs woh ,won roF
.tnemeticxe fo elggirw elttil suounis a sevig eH
deremmah oot teg ot su tnaw t’nod I esuaceb ,guj attocarret eht htiw ffo gnikam erofeb eniw eht htiw retaw xim I oS
,sotpeL dnif dna—
roF	:SAMELOTP !enil doog a saw tahT .no emoc ,hO	 esuaP  .ni ti bur
gniht lacigam ,suoiretsym eht fo terces siht htiw detsurt neeb evah ot yppah smees eH
,spuc eniw fo elpuoc a dna guj a barg nac uoy kniht uoy oD .ytrap eht tA .yeH“
.eno sa detaert eb dna evals a
.oot ,egats-ffo gib taht tsomla si oge siH
.eurt saw mia yM	:NOS EHT ?did...uoY	:NOKILIHP
dnA	:SIKKA  .sgiw gnirts dna sksam lla s’ti esilaer yeht nehT
,egats eht ffo tuB
”?elor txen ruoy rof pu gniklub uoy era rO“ .selbmur eh
noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sotpeL no evom a ekam ot
?ew llahs ,tuo dnif
.su hsuhs ot wap sih spalf sraE giB
eht tub ,thgir tsuj ffo semoc enil a nehw ,dnik doog eht ton—
,lwo eht enehtA naht resiw
.gnuoy era uoY !’taef‘
,lio dna daerb emoS“  !em
,ailahT fo daeh eht sa
?won od ot I ma revetahW !tsaeb ytrid ehT
gnitca drah fo taews eht morf depmulc dna dettam s’ti erehw ruf ym hsurb dna brag evals s’nokilihP fo tuo egnahc I  .em rof sotpeL suoicsul ,ylevol tsuJ
.sodorap eht pu gnidirts ,flesmih sonokyM morf esuoM eht ,sraE giB s’tahT  .nuf
?lliw uoy
.gnol rof uoy rehtob t’now I ,hO“
”!xof ,yeH ?sikkA !sikkA“
!ti yned ot yrt
dna gnidnib sti fo eerf liat
.mra ym rednu daerb fo faol a gnikcut
,detareggaxe serutaef eht
.lla retfa sekoj traf dna seilliw etaicerppa llits od elpoep ekil skooL
tuo gnihtyreve tros ot em evah yeht ykcul s’ti os ,erolag ytitnedi nekatsim dna
…hcihw fo gnikaepS
.seil suomrone sih dna
.uoy evol yeht taht dna
:sraE giB tuoba gniht eht s’tahT
.won egatsno si sotpeL
”.melborp oN“  .sdda eh
,suoires yldaed s’eH .noissap
,esuom roop a htiw evol ni s’ohW
.rotca na hcuot ot gnitnaw elpoep esoht llA“ .elbaroda s’tI
oS	:NOS EHT !kcots tselbon eht fo si esuom ydal eht ees nac I !sey
.gnitca fo trap si spahsim eseht hguorht gnisivorpmi tub
?sroolf gnipeews dna sehsid gnihsaw
.nmuloc reh no pu
em gnisu s’eh taht
,evol gnuoy fo yrots a
,llew trap eht syalp eh tub ,tar a yllautca s’eH
”!sonokyM morf esuoM
,tseuqer a gnikam tnacilppus a ekiL
!NOIL a era UOY...tuB
,nmuloc reh no ailahT woleb ,ssarg eht no tops a esoohc I
gnuoY	 :NOKILIHP TEERTS EHT :ENECS ***  .sotpeL htiw enecs gib eno ym :ti si sihT
I fi dnim t’now uoY	:REHTAF EHT !ksa tsuJ