,retne ot suoregnad oot raf saw tI
.margaid_enoz_gnidnaL
,elttil a frus eht otni tuo teg
hsirebbig tsuj s’tI
,efil lamina fo noitavresbo tcerid on tey sA
,diulf a sa elbaulaV
:si noitseuq eht ,ecneH
,kool a teg t’ndid druM
.su tcerroc ot fi sA
.ti stih thgil eht nehw slewej ekil selkraps ti dna
.desumeb ,ffo ylf yeht
,erutsiom morf nori eht tcetorp ot tnaem saw siht ylbamuserP
,yrtne siht etirw I sa nevE
.rehtaew suodrazah morf retlehs draobpihs gniriuqer fo ytilautneve eht rof eraperp lliW
.tcatnoc ot enoyna fo kcal eht yb delbuort s’ye kniht I
,dnal ot erehwemos gnidnif fo sepoh eht ni
,ezam sihT .lla ti ni tsol
”yawA raF hctertS sdnaL leveL dna enoL ehT“
?ecnaraeppasid rieht desuac evah dluow tahW ?yeht era erehW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.enif saw ti dna ,eno detset dna retfa suovren tlef I ,yrrow t’noD
.kcirt eht od dluohs eldduc dekan ecin A
,yawyna seilf ti teY
,floWcaM boR dna lufraF lacsaP yb
dias dna uoy ot pu deklaw enoemos fi sA
,su fo raef on evah ot mees yehT
.ti htiw hguorht og d’ye kniht t’ndid I
,meht gnideen etapicitna I taht toN
.sirbed eticlac dna slatem fo reyal eht pota worg ot elbanu dna detnuts ,seert tub nihtiw gnihton dnuof eW
:seert eht naht gnitseretni ssel
.srethgierf muileh eht toN
.niaga raeppasid ot ylno
.lufituaeb s’ti syas nlaF
rof gnitiaw em tpek druM  !noows
.sksullom ro sdoporhtra fo snoisurtxe evitcnitsni eht neeb evah dluoc esehT
!gnizama si yE !gnizama saw tI
,elcatnet wap
.metsys rats eht dehcaorppa neve ew erofeb maeb oidar enal a dellems d’I ecnis sruoh elpuoc a neeb ydaerla d’tI
.dnuos gnimmurht a ecudorp yeht tsaf os sgniw sti gnitaeb
,derats ew dna doots ew dnA
.gnipporctuo eht fo stnemele eht no delwarcs stxet yltcnitsid yrev erew erehT
:sroloc fo yarra na ni
,noitacav rof stenalp detrahcnu ot og ot teg t'nod yeht yhw wonk ot tnaw ohw
!gnizilibats/gnitartenep/elam os
serehps etilletas ro
,secnamor elat-tirips tneicna eht lla ni ekil tsuj dna ,did ye tuB
emoib a ni edixonom negordyhid fo ecnedive fo tol A
,deticxe nehw tuB
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots sihT
!dednal ev’eW !puyA
sa luftekcub a derehtag I
,detnaw I revetahw erolpxe ot eerf leef dluohs I dias yE
.deticxe yrev saw I .yllanif
,tcatnoc ot ereh enoyna si ereht fi taht skniht druM
.tiurf a eta I .si ydobon ekiL
.esoprup euqse-itiffarg ,laiciffonu na gnivah sa meht terpretni dluow I
,sgniw tnerapsnarT
,meht revo swolb dniw eht nehW
.sniur erom yllaitnetoP
,ytivitca cimsies tsap fo ecnedive latibrO :scinotceT
:ti ot detpada smees noitategev emos hguoht
,laicifitra evorp serutcurts eseht fi nevE
.tnatsnocni revoc duolC
toor a revo debmilc ew
*** gnp.ecnanoser_tengam_nacs_elgnuj gnp.lacihpargopot_nacs_elgnuj gnp.oidar_peed_nacs_elgnuj :TNEMHCATTA ELIF druM—
,sseltneler os ,yreif os ,etanoissap os saw yE
,taht dnatsrednu yeht ecno dna
.dehsilbatse eb dluohs snoitaler citamolpid hcihw htiw mrof efil tnanimod a si ereht fi enimreted ot tpmettA :noissiM .enoN
.slamina ylno tcaf ni era eseht edulcnoc tsum I
,meht fo tuo esir slamina enrobria deroloc ylthgirb fo smraws dna
,ydob sti ot noitroporp ni ,llams oot mees sgniw stI
.su evoba weiv otni esae yxalag eht dehctaw dna dnas eht ni rehtegot delgguns eW
gnihtemos s’ereht tuB
.laicifitra eb ot evorp lliw tcepsus osla I hcihw
.sdipar otni snrut revir eht erehw yb nwod
.t’ndid I dnA htaerb peed
.desufnoc werg yeht
!me saw erolpxe ot detnaw I tahw taht dias tsomla I
.etuc er’yeht skniht nlaF
?koob a yllautca saw gniht siht dna ’daer‘
?elpoep siht fo ymonoce eht fo sisab eht saw ti spahreP
.siht tliub sgnieb laicos
.pihs eht fo tuo emoc t’ndluow druM
.dnas fo edam dna xelpmoc yrev si roiretni eht
.krab rieht no gniworg efil tnalp rehto evah meht fo tsegral eht taht hcus elacs a no
.no taht htiw stenalp rof nommoc s’taht
…ni dna ,ria eht ni nehW
.sedis rieht hguorht snagro lanretni rieht nees evah dluoc I
.pam_tnemelttes_elgnuj :TNEMHCATTA ELIF druM—
!taht tenalp siht deman I yhw s’tahT
.silopolagem etercnoc dna leets siht
.fo wonk ew naht ereh no gniog reggib gnihtemos eb thgim ereht ekil leef ot gnitrats si nlaF neve noisserpmi eht teg I
!tcafitra llams a dnuof I dna
.gnol sehcni owt tuoba egareva no ydoB
…fo otnemem a gnivah htrow noomyenoh a eb ll’ereht fi wonk t’nod I
!2 yaD noomyenoH *** druM—
.snrettap eb tsum tahw ni sroloc gnitfihs dna sdrohc gniyalp era yehT
cimarec citsuac yldlim fo mrof emos fo serutcurts
.ereh eb ot desoppus ton m’I ekiL .ddo
,dniw ralos fo tnecs yb ylelos gnitagivan erew eW
meht ot gnitseretni erom on mees ew
,tsigoloehcra na ton
,tol a sneppah taht druM dnuora dna
.eergasid tonnac I
.noitcerid yreve ni ees nac I sa raf sa gnihcterts seert fo aes a fo tuo esor tI
:slevel noitaidaR
,sdnif dilos erom fo smret nI ?swonk ohw os
.dekan sgniht rehto od nehT
,slavretni cinomrah ni syawla
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT    druM—
.gniyrt yad elohw a detsaw I
.tbuod on ,su yb debrutsiD
,yltnereffid dednob s’tI
.gninaem evah dluoc siht yleruS
,ymedaca eht morf gnilraey a sa
,gnipporctuo ralugerri na si erehT
.ecnegilletni sa wonk dluow ew tahw ylpmi ylirassecen ton seod erutcetihcra xelpmoc
era erehT .detibahni ecno saw tenalp siht taht tnedifnoc m’I
.peels ot elba eb ll’I erofeb elttil a nwod dniw ot deen I !wonk uoy ,llew
,netfo os yreve elprup dna der fo skcelf htiw
,stserofniar dnalwol eht gnitrahc detrats ev’eW
,gnol a koot I .ev’dluohs I
,etihw s’ti ,nat tsuj t’nsi dnas ehT
,selgnuj nisab eseht fo eno ni eb lliw meht gnidnif ta ecnahc tseb ruo neht
?ti htiw od ot gnihtemos evah htilonom siht spahrep seod dnA
,thgin ta siht devresbo I fi tcepsus I
,neerg fo sedahs tnereffid ytriht ekil dna
,hcihw fo gnikaepS
.doporhtra enrobria na si tI
,seirutnec eht revo deliaf sah tub
.rettil fael eht ni gnirettiks oN .gnosdrib oN
)?enog gnol won ,siht pota reyal rehtona saw ereht spahrep(
.tcnitsni naht erom gnihtyna fo tcudorp eht era yeht esnes eht ni laicifitra erew yeht naem t’nseod taht
.daehrevo gnilcric ,sgniw lufecarg gnol htiw gnihtemoS
..nogard delcatcepseb eht ,mrywkooB irikeneN yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR dna lufraF lacsaP yb
,emoh kcab naht reitlas yaw s’naeco ehT
,kcab nrut dluohs ew yas ot tuoba saw I nehw tsuJ
.ti edisni yrtiucric fo ecnedive wohs ot mees seod
.noitacol siht morf raf ton
.segap yrruFoS evitcepser rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,sgnittif dna tnemssobme sti fo rennam eht yb gnigduj tub
.skrow eht ni hcnerw a nworht sah yrevocsid s’nlaF  thgiE ruoF enO nijaZ pelA yrtnE *** nlaF—
)hud ,pihs eht morf trapa(
.lufituaeb ylgnikaerbtraeh si tenalp sihT…srotsecna ,hO
’,noitazilivic tsol‘ yas ot tsrif eht saw ,nlaF ,etam yM
.ti fo etats eht morf gnigduj ,tsael ta ,seirutnec emos roF
,ytiniciv etaidemmi eht ni hcum llems t’naC
,smra owt ,sgel ruof
.reduol su ot ydolem eht yalp ,rO
.dekan miws ,onnud I ho
,swen suoires erom nI !yarooH
,yltnaillirb ecsediri yeht
,citnamor dnuos t’nseod taht fi dnA
.yrd erew ew dna nwod saw rats eht llit ,ruf s’rehtohcae ni dniw eht leef ,ti ediseb teknalb a no eil d’ew ,hcaeb eht no erifpmac a ekam d’I neht dnA
:emoh kcab sdnal krap eht morf ecnereffid dnuoforp a sekam tI
,smrof efil yb tliub esoprup erew yeht taht esnes eht ni
,smsinagro tnailer-edixonom negordyhid fo tol a ees ot gnitcepxE
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
ereht nwod s’tahw fo sisylana ycnaf emos enod sah druM
,hcaeb lautca eht ot nwod pihs eht koot eW *** gnp.pam_tnemelttes_elgnuj
.gnihtyreve dna epocs eht htiw ti detset neve I tub
.stnemelttes detibahni yllaitnetoP
.ti ta skool ydobon fi rettam t’nseod taht …ekil tub
.noisserpxe fo tros esnesnon-on lacizziuq a htiw daeh
!gnidnaL noomyenoH *** gnp.margaid_enoz_gnidnaL
.setis gnidnal eht fo tser eht nalp-er ot hcraeser od ot dedeen ye
.stnemele emas eht yllacimehc
.egdir ynots a no niaga dednal eW
.yllufgninaem etacinummoc nac ew hcihw htiw gnihtemos ton tub
,tenalp siht no enola yletelpmoc erew ew taht
?peelsa neeb ev’thgim tI
.foor a emoceb ot pot eht drawot sevruc hcihw
.raf siht tuo serutnev ydoboN
.gnorw yleritne ton eb ton yam ye dna
.erehpsimeh nrehtron eht fo
!tcelloc dna dnif ot sgniht
:swollof sa sisylana laitinI
aera gnigats tcefrep a neeb evah thgim ti neht
.emoh kcab nedrag eht ni emos tuorps nac I ebyaM ”.selpmas“
,wonk I taht noitaiva fo swal lla ot gnidroccA
,gnipporctuo eht ta dnuof ew smeti rehto eht era deedni sa ,kcordeb naht rewen raf ti si ylno toN
ytpme esuoh eht dna
.laicifitra ylekil er’yeht yas ylefas nac I kniht I neht
.doog ytterp detsat tI
,tniaf yllaudividni si sihT
.drah oot gnikrow s’ye kniht I
,sgnipporctuo enots gnikool driew eseht s’erehT
thgil laicifitra yna neve ton s’erehT
,yolla nobrac dna nori na ,lateM
,telbat eht pu dekcip
,dezilaer tsuj ylno d’I fi sa ,tuo tniop neht
.srats eht enihstuo ot
.sgniht ta kool a gnikat nageb dna gnipporctuo eht ot tuo yaw ruo edam eW
,dnuora eldduh ot meht desuac sihT
.won detceted gnihton tub
.ecruos doof rieht eb tsum ratcen ro tiurf tcepsus I
,elosnoc ym no dnal emos
elgnuj tnadrev dna hsul siht hguorht gniklaw ,eiree saw tI
yad lla koot tI enO pelA
.noisorroc negyxo ot elbitpecsus erutcurts eht gnivael
.erehpsomta tnanimod-negyxO :scirehpsomtA
.meht ot cisum deyalp
.lla retfa ,noomyenoh a eb ot desoppus SI sihT
,raewmiws eht ni su teg annog saw I !efas s’tI
.ti no txet dessobme na dna gnirutxet thgils emos htiw ,ti ot noitrop ”kcab“ reporp a sah dna kciht s’ti tub
?won yeht era erehw oS
2 fo 1 traP
.knub eht no peelsa pu delruc s’druM
,foor/llaw devruc rehtona saw erehT
!yaw eht ni teg ot sgnir neve ro
,snacs roiretxe morf ti nees t’ndah ew esruoc fO
elttil a pu nethgil t’now etam ym fi hguohT
,dlrow llams a s’ti tub
hcum dnA .gnipporctuo kcor eht naht
.snoitaraperp s’ye morf druM tcartsid og yllaer dluohs I
.retal detaroprocni gnihtemos ton
:stnevE lacigoloroeteM
,neerG ,esiouqruT ,eulB ,deR
.seiceps suoibihpma na ylpmi thgim sihT
.sdnoces eerht yreve ecno fo etar egareva na ta gnignahc
,sniur eht no sgnidaer ycnaf emos did druM
smroftalp tisnart latibro on s’ereht dna ,sreyal ni meht hctac sduolc eht dna ,snorffas dna selprup ,sdlog dna sder
.sgnillewd laudividni ylbamuserP
.sragus dna snimativ tsuJ
.deraperp eb ot llew s’ti tub
…neht tub ,netsil ot mraws
.nihtiw smoor rellams elpitlum fo ecnedive ees did ew tub
llits dloh ot meht fo yna nettog evah dluoc I fi tcepsus I
,neveS evlewT niyA pelA yrtnE *** nlaF- !ykoopS
sesnes cirtemortcele dah yeht ebyam
,yxalag eht fo edis siht htiw railimaf ton m’I
,morf pu deyek oot llits m’I
,ot erew ew fi ees ot ydobon saw ereht dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,stroppus egdirb elbissoP
.wow hO *** ntc.sgnidaeroib_nacs ntc.ygolohprom_nacs
.erehwon fo elddim eht ni tuo reve ti si wow dnA
.retaw eht fo tuo ro ni ssecca ysae rof
.ysub s’ye elihw ,tuo kcehc annaw I ecalp eno ees diD
skcolf suomrone eht ssorca sroloc tnereffid fo sevaw secudorp hcihw
.nwod yaw eht lla tilps dna dekcarc ,nekorb dna derehtiw d’yehT
!ereh stnirptoof evael ot sgnieb tneitnes tsrif eht er’ew ebyaM .ydoboN
.enil suounitnoc ylegral a demrof llaw sti os pu denil tub
,erolpxe ot sdnas dna selgnuj fo ytnelP
,senot tnereffid yalp lliw kcolf eht nihtiw spuorg tnereffiD
.ecnatsid eht ni tsud fo emulp gib a ,stug s’ti otni peed delbmurc dna delbbow ecnatsid raf eht ni seno eht fo eno ,llew sa tsuj
,tceffe larutcetihcra ehT
,dica ciruflus ,yrucrem on ,snixot yldaed oN
,foorp etulosba tey ton evah I elihW
esingocer nac I tpircs ro egaugnal yna ni ton s’tI
,sselroloc ylegral si ydob eht ,treni nehW
.llew sa suonimul eb ot evorp dluow yeht
.tey ereh morf dessenrah neeb t’ndah ti desirprus m’I
.ecnatsbus eht otni devrac ton ,sreyal lacirtemmysa ni dettamrof era yehT
tnardauq reppu eht ni dnas eht no edam gnidnaL
,yna sa mret a doog sa si ’skcolf‘ esoppus I
,revir eht tsdima dna dnuora
ew nehw ”sseccus“ llac dluoc I gniht tsesolc eht dah eW
,sisylana no rehtaew gnildduc gnizama hcus etsaw ot emirc a eb dluohs ti dnA
llaw egral a si edis eno no erutcurts ehT
,tnerruc elttil a ti evig
,yawa revoh yeht dna ffo meht hsurb I llit ,suoivilbo
.ti tae ot gnihtemos dnetni tsum yeht
:tnerapsnart neve
!ylevol skool ti dna
.hcaeb eht nwod deklaw I daetsnI
.erohsaes eht teem selgnuj eht erehw gnola nwod ebyam ro
.srekcurt eht toN
.snoitamrof cigoloeg no noisore diuqil dna dniw htob fo ecnedivE
,eborp renetsil emit toh detamotua na saw
detraped lla kcap ym dnif ot
.elbidua yltcnitsid s’ti
.noitategev evisnetxE :lacigoloiB
,kcordeb eht naht rewen yltnacifingis er’yeht fI .yllacigoloidar
!stuanortsa tseilrae eht ekil
.elgnuj siht tsael ta tuohguorht cifilorp eb ot smees taht seiceps lamina na
.ygolohprom_nacs
.ezinomrah yeht dnA
,emoh emoc ev’I fi sa sleef tI
!em ksa uoy fi ,larutan eb ot delgna-thgir oot elttil a meeS
fo sgnidaer dna snoitavresbo era dehcattA .ytisrevidoib erom raf sah etis gnidnal dnoces ehT enO pelA teB yrtnE *** nlaF—
,pihs eht ni kcab telbat eht dah dna snacs s’ye demrofrep
:TNEMHCATTA ELIF druM— .dloc dna
.slacimehc emas eht ,erom rO
etutitsni eht ta pu segelloc yhpargollets eht ta sgnirts dellup ye teb I .eno su dnuof ye woh wonk t’nod I
,floWcaM boR dna lufraF lacsaP yb
thgit os em dnuora smra sye tup yE .etarepsed
.tnacifingisni toN
.seert eht revo derevoh taht
,telbat eht nepo dekcarc gnivah ,tub
,sie ni skool druM woh ees dluohs uoY
.nialp eht ssorca gnitfaw ti dnes I
.serutcurts leets ,llaT  .serutcurtS
.doolb dna hself emas eht fo ton era elpoep eseht dna htilonom eht spahreP
.rehtie no sgnidaer doog teg t’nac ew stcejbo rehto dnuora gniworg era dna kciht era seert eht hguoht
,ereh si ereht dnas hcum woh nevig hguohT
d’I nwod ti evil em tel reven d’ye wonk t’ndid I fI
.anuaf fo dnuos on gniraeh dna
!lamina na was I erus
.yawa tpews teg ot em tnaw t’ndid ye ekiL
,serutcurts eht fo yna retne t’ndluoc eW
.nesohc d’ye tenalp tahw htiw segaaaaa
,em raeh ,srotsecnA .elpoep toN
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ti ot tseraen esoht fo roloc eht hctam ot yrt ot smees laudividni hcae
,eert eht ni gnittis lamina gnirehtils ,gnol a saw erehT
.pu lla ti derevoc dah seert eht
.worromot emos teem ew fi erus rof wonk ll’ew sseug I
…leef em sekam enola ti ni tuo gnieB
,serutcip teg ot rebmemer dna yrt ll’I
dedrocer reve ev’ew tcatnoc ylno eht syas ye dna
,yrtneer gnitrats erew ew elihw nevE
.esnes sekam tahT
,lassoloc era seert ehT
.driht a eb ot ssam thgir eht fo sirbed fo elip a dna
.yrt ot etis wen a deifitnedi ev’I tub
.krad gnitteg saw ti dna ssorca devom dah rats eht
”yawA raF hctertS sdnaS leveL dna enoL ehT“
,seno lacirdnilyc egral owt erew erehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.elgnuj eht otni tnecsed eht rof stiusirips dennoD eniN eviF waW eH teB yrtnE *** nlaF—
.muidem noitacinummoc a eb dluoc siht yleruS
.suoivilbo sa tsuj
ruoF enO niS pelA yrtnE *** nlaF— !hguone gnol druM fo ffo swap ym peek nac dna deticxe oot ton m’I gnimussa
,ti ssorca eldnurt
.citnamor eht saw I thguoht I
,suoegrog era ereh stesrats eht esuaceb ,ysub ssel eb ot emit emos dnif retteb d’ye me dlot I .ezylana ot pihs eht otni kcab meht gnikat si dna selpmas dnas emos detcelloc sah druM .gnirutnevda dna gnirednow emos gniod neeb ev’eW !ohwynA !agoowa
.elttil a me tcartsid ot yrt annoG
.nobrac ot dednoB
noitisop tneserp sti ni hguohT
.dloG ,atnegaM ,elpruP
,noitcnuf on evres ot smees ti
,hO ?esle gnihtemos ot tcennoc ot desoppus saw ti ebyaM
.etis eht dnuora elbisiv erew serutcurts latem-detsurc eticlac ,rellams ,rehtO
.su fo tnorf ni thgir ,saw ti ereh tuB
!ot klat nac I tahT
,tiurf gniraeb era yeht fi
.tnuoma orez-non a tub
,tnegilletni taht dnim ym ni tbuod on s’erehT
.sehtolc hcaeb ruo gnola thguorb ew dalg I ma yob dna ereh ydnas s’tI
,mH“ og dna ,shtap tiucric tnereffid eht leef
.denodnaba tuB
.nlaF ,yrrow t’noD
:TNEMHCATTA ELIF .druM— .eunitnoc ot goL
.meht gnikat em dnim ot mees t’ndid ti tub
.dednecsed ew sa desaerced llems noitaidar ehT
.meht no delwarcs stxet esoht dna sisylana eht morf setad eht morf htob
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.tey noitidepxe siht egavlas ll’I
.srallip neeb ecno evah ot mees taht
:efil tnegilletni htiw tcatnoC
.diarfa saw ye ekil tub—erus
,edis eht no stols eseht fo eno otni ,onnud I
.gnihtyna ro enieffac ro
!seod tahw wonk t’nod I neht
,gnitanicsaf dna ,seno lufituaeB
.ti etavitca ro nepo ti teg druM ro I nac roN
,esu ni dna wen saw erutcurts siht nehw
.ereh devil I fi evil ot tnaw d’I erehw s’tahT
,renedrag a m’I tuB
.rof gnikool neeb d’ew noitasilivic ehT
.erus rof s’taht ,gnitirw fo mrof emos fo elbapac elpoep a erew esehT
,esaelp sey ,hcihw—
eno niam regral eht morf detarapes
.enola yllufitip os leef em sekam taht tenalp siht tuoba gnihtemos si ereht rof
”yawA raF hctertS sdnaS leveL dna enoL ehT“   yojne esaelP
sgnipporctuo cimarec citsuac eseht fo emos etad ot tpmetta lliw I
,dnas eht ffo depiw I ecno derorrim si tnorf stI
.erew yeht ereht dna
!noitazilivic tsol a fo sniur tneicna s’ti teb I
!oga sraey derdnuh owt ekil saw taht dna
.meht nekat sah noitidepxe siht erehw sa llew sa ,woh dna
!tsaf eb tsum ti oS
.retal kool a evah nac ew os pihs eht ni kcab ti tup I
:yletelpmoc su dragersid osla yeht tub
!feirb miws eht tuo nekorb s’druM
.ria eht otni ti teg ot
,ereh yteicos a saw ereht wohs sgnipporctuo ehT
.detseretninu neht ,erusnU
retaw gniwolf ekil ssot sehcnarb eht
.nogard delcatcepseb eht
.meht ni sgniht ecnerefer ssorc ,niaga sotohp latibro sye lla hguorht kcab og ot dedeen ye dias yE
!enif os si ereh dnuora dnas ehT ?etirima
yeht woh saw sepahs tnereffid otni wolf stnerruc gnileef dna
,eulb dna ,dlog dna
.tsurc eticlac ralugerri yldeggaj a htiw detaoc
.tnecifingam neeb evah tsum
”!elaT gnillirhT A ,sey hO ,hA
,htilonom eht gnillac m’I tahw s’taht ,rorriM ehT
level aes tsap rehgih a sezisehtopyh eno fi
,noitidepxe eht egavlas
.”doof eht tae toh tuo fo nehw doof dloc eht nevo od yhW“
…tub detaehrepus ylekil
.sdnuow gnipag ekil meht fo tuo devaelc neeb dah seloh giB
,sniur eht ta kool ot enog d’ew emit eht yB
!epoh ot em deripsni taht roivaheb ylno eht ton saw sihT
.ylf ot elba eb ton dluohs erutaerc siht
ytterP .rekciht era selgnuj eht dna stnalp eht erehw nwod rehtruf erehwemos ot ffo evom ew erofeb sdnalhgih tresed eht ni yad tsal ruo eb ylekil lliw worromoT
,esruoc fo ,suoegrog s’tI
…elttil a ekil kcits dluow yeht ekiL
,ti ni noitaidar fo secart llems nac I dna
,noitcurtsnoc sti fo trap suoicsnoc a neeb evah ot demees ti
,etam ym ot sserts ot dah evah I sa tuB
!ecalp siht gniman m’I tahw s’taht esuaceB
,gaw a liat ym evig I emit yrevE
!setam laiciffo sa rehtegot tca tsrif ruo sa dlrow detrahcnu ylsuoiverp a no ,era ew ereh
,gnihtyna raeh t’ndid taht
.taht enod evah t’ndluohs repus I
!efil tnegilletni si siht yleruS
,skcolf egral ni ,niaga tub
lmiG yrtnE *** nlaF—
?ylppus tem evah ton thgim dnamed
.sdael emos me def yeht dna
.ti saw sihT .sihT
.retaw fo ydob yna dessorc ecno evah ot denoitisop mees tsegral eht ylno hguoht
…tlef thginot tuoba gnihtemos tub
,deedni ,od yeht fi tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,enif s’ye stsisni yE .deirrow elttil a em sah
.noitnetta sye tog I emit eht yb enog saw ti
,cimarec citsuac emas eht fo desopmoc yltsom osla
.surohc naibihpma oN
,ereh gnihtyreve ekil