,dias eh ,tfel eh erofeB
tnaem ylno yllanigiro flesti drow eht taht
.raet a pu egnuorcs neve t'ndid lived ehT
.nam edam-fles emoselohw siht
htog deriah-kcalb siht ,yllanif nehT
,”edirP aigroeG ot nwoD tneW liveD ehT“
,tneve eht ro nis eht rehtie
.elbat 'stifsim eht ta yad a tsal reven d'eh
,edirP yppaH .remrahC
.gnimool si hturt eht zuc
.yad yreve sdik gnillik snug dna swal
.enola sedir reven yrtogiB
.seye rieht dellor ylthgir lla seiddaD dna sneeuQ ehT
,eman s'yddaD yloH ym ni dnA .skcirb emos dna
meht revo dekcinap
gnirebmemer htrow si ti
.TRC tuob' mi' llet ew nehw
.od ot ssa ruoy devom sah tsirhC tahw si siht teY
,edam evah uoy taht dlrow eht si lleH"
yojne esaelP  ’.ymene‘
edirP aigroeG ot nwod tnew lived ehT  EFH yb meop a
.gnitcepxe erew yeht elbib eht gnivah ton
.me' setah yddaD yloH ruo hcum woh s'tahT
,gnimriuqs-a tog trautS  ."ma'am"
.deepsdog me' hsiw neve t'nod
eniuqE eht ,foohnorI nok’aT yb uoy rof daer ,EFH yb
!nemA .mia ruoy sselb
,eman 'suseJ ni live seod enoemos nehW
.nam dlo ym naht redlo koob rehtael a gnivaw eit dna
seirots reaf fo erom dnif
thgir epiws rieht zuc eerf-tocS ffo gnitteg sreredrum siH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
.legna nmad a spup ruo fo hcae
".regna fo ecalp a morf gnikaeps er'uoy ekil dnuos uoY
.syag su nopu tsaf pu gnimoc erew syad eriflleh gnihceercs detrats eH
"!uoy si edirP ta ereh lived ylno eht ,riS
”edirP aigroeG ot nwoD tneW liveD ehT“ saw sihT
gnitcepsersid lived eht
era sehcruhc sih ,elihwnaeM
,srekcits ssecca noitroba
.toh ythgim repmet sih tog
,ris ,gninnur tratS
era srotsap ruoY
em thguat rotsap yM
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
lived eht fo tpecnoc eht sa dedaol sA
trihs deralloc a gniraew
!smacs dna semirc fo sdnik lla pu gnirevoc
,kniwt htog a flesruoy teg oS
trautS gnillac no peek tsuj d'eh teY
,relevart wollef ruoy
nac uoY .ssalc gnihtimsrevlis reaf ni loohcs hgih ni kcab htnoM eht fo tsitrA now ecno ohw ,EFH yb
traeh s'lived taht sesselb esle enoemos epoh I oS
.ereh netsil ,nos ,woN"
rieht pleh ot sexat gniyap neve ton dnA
zuc ralupop s'eh ykcul s'lived ehT  .klof wollef
.gnithgif emoceb t'ndid regna taht elcarim a saw tI
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
.gnimoorg laer eht gniod
.moc.orpEFH no
.hcruhc ot lived eht ekat ot eugnot sih desu eH
,lleh sa etilop lla erew eW
.hgih os etar edicius 'sklof sih htiw yad a tsal reven d'eH
ti deen annog s'eh zuc
,edirP sa hcus cipot a htiw noitcnujnoc ni seirrac ti sa snoitpmussa ynam sa dna ,emoceb sah
.ythgim dna hgih gnitca lived eht htiw tahW