,pu dekcip stsug ehT
meht htiw daerb kaerb ot ytiliba eht uoy detnarg evah yeht rof
.saw dlihc eht tnuag woh yb deyamsiD
.llaw eht tsniaga gnimmalS
.llih eht pu gnimmurd emac sevooh gnipollag tnatsid fo dnuos eht litnu gnol t'nsaw tI
.od dluow dlihc yna tahw od dluow eh oS
.taorht sih gnihcnelc
.tnereffid eb dluow thgin siht tuB
.knits dirtup a tsuj htiw flesmih dnefed t’ndluoc eh tuB
worra na htiw redluohs sih gnihctulc
dna romra detalp yvaeh
.sgiwt dna sdeew deird fo hctap eht deflugne ylkciuq taht erif eht morf gnitanimullI
.lluks sih hguorht deohce deredrum neeb dah ohw namsdraug dnoces eht fo sdrow ehT
.niaga gnignol eht emac nehT
,retsis reh morf deppir reverof noom elap eht rof tpew eH
.daeh etihw yggahs s’deyomaS gnuoy eht fo pot no flesti dexif
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
tcaf eht saw lla ti fo trap tsrow ehT
.dnah ni llits daeL
.nees reve dah eh nam yna naht lassoloc erom raF
gib sa tuoba saw mih fo tnorf ni dleh eh wap degadnab ehT
.dnal gnidnuorrus eht gnitanimulli ,sllaw eht gnola ezalba seniv dna stoor eht gnitteS
.rewot eht fo tuo yaw rieht edam yeht sa
.denodnabA .enola dna dloc
?notyalC tuoba s’woH“
.erofeb meht ekil enoyna nees reven d’eH
,rood eht rof kaerb a ekaM
”.ecnadiug dna thgil ruoy ot flesym etoved I
.ecam sih fo dne eht htiw hself sih nopu rehtaF eht fo ecitsuj eht detceriD
,dehcnilf yob eht ,resolc tog eh nehW
.detcejretni ylkciuq raeb nworb eht
.thgiliwt eht detah eh yhw si hcihW
.ereh erew nem eseht yhw rednow mih edam
eht dna ,wap s’yob llams eht no pirg sih desolc yltneg dna delims enisru ehT
.reyarp sih desolc eh sa
.htiw werg yob eht nem ylno ehT
guh mraw s’notgnihtrA hguorht etib dluoc tsorf retniw eht neve toN
”rewoT ehT“   yojne esaelP
.ydob elttil yffulf sih fo rebif yreve htiw deyarP
.dnal dna saes fo dog rotagivaN
.deppots ylneddus seirc sih dna
.maerd a eb ot dah sihT
.raeh uoy tahw yojne ev’uoy fi esoht rof tuokool eht no eb os sretpahc erom eerht edulcni
,reggad sih deveirter dna nwod dehcaeR
.dnuorg eht no sselhtaerb yal yeht ,won tuB   .driht A
.stsug gnorts eht
roreuqnoC eht nam siht saW .dnik siH
.htiaf eht fo lobmys eht saw ti ,tnaem ti tahw wenk yob ehT
.emit siht reduol ,htruof A
?gnimaerd eh saW ?laer siht saW
sgnul sih dellif nmutua fo secips prahs ehT
.yretsym a saw gnol siht devivrus yob niht eht woH
erofeb semit ruof nwod ti thguorb eH
.tnereffid gnihtemos deciton eh ,seye sih denepo eh nehW
nus eht selat eht wonk ot hsiw I
.ti yb dednuorruS .nihtiw morf
.llew oot lla wenk eh dallab a saw tI
.etunim a naht ssel ni revo lla saw tI
,uoy nopu delims evah sdoG eht yadot ,lleW“ .dekrims ylzzirg ehT   ”!?ecaf ym ot eil siht llet ot yretnorffe eht evah
.rehtoM eht morf ycrem rof geb oT
.rekihhctiH flowereW
.od dluoc eh esle gnihton
,floW ynnaD yb ”rewoT ehT“ saw sihT       .tser nac eh
ruf sih no ylthgirb os denrub syar reH
dna ni daeh sih dekop raeb ehT
,tnatsid erew yehT
emoc lliw taht srehto ynam dna yrots trohs siht tuo kcehc nac uoy ,won roF .nolavA
,s’notgnihtrA no ylluferac ti decalp
”rewoT ehT“ si yrots s’yadoT dna ,rellevarT wolleF ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.srae sih tsniaga dednuop petstoof htfif ehT
.sehtolc sih gnipolevne ydaerla saw taht erif eht gnidiova
.tsehc sih ot pu wap sih thguorb neht eh
.nosirapmoc ni elucsunim saw hcihw
,kees I revlis yreve
.reviR ehtnyraL eht gnola sdnal eht nopu
.denodnabA .enola dna dloC
.ydob sih hguorht srevihs tnes dniw eht fo gnilwoh eht
.dereviled saw enon tub
.eralf dna taeh eht yb dessapmocne saw elbuod sih nooS
.sllawenots s’rewot eht ta deppihw retniw fo sdniw ehT
.yob eht htiw seye dekcol neht eH
.duola delkcuhc ylzzirg egral a
egeis dial noitcaf tsitarapes a taht denrael eh sa noos sa su tneS“
.enots dna nori dellihc fo sraey ynam eht ekorb taht ecarbme nA
.nepo ediw gnulf dna gnirettahs ,ni evag rood ehT
.nwod rood eht kaerb ot nageb raeb eht sa ria eht ssorca deyarps tsud dna sretnilpS
.drows sih fo lemmop eht no denetsaf mlap siH
.denodnabA .enola dna dloC
.elzzum sih nwod dezoo doolb dna
.enutrof fo dna kcul fO
ot eud yllacidarops dehsarht thgil sti sa dnuorg eht gnissiK
,gnihtolc fo eceip yreve no denrad saw taht lobmys eht
.deunitnoc raeb eht ,sgel sih no pu yob eht gnitteg
.ytimixorp rieht etipsed ,nem rehto eht yb decitonnu ylgnimeeS
.llew sa gnizeerf saw noom eht fi derednow semitemos eH
,doolb sih no dekohc nam niht eht sa rorroh ni dehctaw yob ehT
.siht fo lla rof esuac eht s’eH .siht did eH
,rats detniop-enin a htiw rennab a deirrac
.pal sih no swap sih detser
denediw htuom sih sa dlihc eht htiw seye gnihctac ylgnimees
.gnilffins ,mih ta derats tsuj dlihc ehT
.gnitfird ydaerla saw eh ;dias eh tahw raeh t’ndluoc notyalC
.ecarg reh ni reh nioj ot elba eb reven lliw htob yeht taht ezilaer ot ylnO
,tils eht hguorht doolf osla dluow stsug ehT
.edih ot ecalp a rof gnikool
.taht ssecorp ot woh wonk t’ndid yob ehT
ylwolS .ti koot ylsuoituac yob eht hcihw ot
.gniees ot demotsucca nworg dah eh sdraug eht sa sroloc emas eht raew t’ndid yehT
.tsaerb s’mar eht otni edalb eht gnivird dna mutnemom eht gniunitnoc
”!ssenisub ruoy etatS“   .gnirekcib rieht
,deraeppasid erif gnigar ehT
.stnap etihw deniats-dum
.deriuqni raeb egral ehT
.tilsworra worran eht no swap sih decalp dna seenk htob no llef yob deyomaS ehT
,mar a ,draug rehtonA
elihw gnihton otni gnitaropave dna gnirrahc ruf etihW
.kcen sih gnola dna tleb tsiaw sih morf demmirb ruf rebmU
.flesmih ot derepsihw yob eht ”…yad enO“
.esproc s’flow eht revo gnidnats flesmih fo noisrev rehto eht dehctaw ylsseldnim yob ehT
notgnihtrA ”.htrae eht htiw gnola yalp lla d’ew dna
.onrefni na otni thgin eht gnitteS
desu I .tnemelttes yalc egral a no tliub saw ecalp siht ,wonk uoY“
.dum deird dna yah yarts htiw derettil saw rebmahc ehT
dewolleb sedalb fo gnihceercs ehT
.nur ot yob eht ta gnimaercs saw bmil yrevE
?noitanicullah siht morf ekaw eh t’nac yhW ?dne ti t’now yhw tuB .noos dne ot sah taht eramthgin a nI .peelsa s’eH
.ruf sih dna ecaf sih derevoc triD
,krad dennod yehT
.tneserp syawla yaced fo hcnets eht gnikam ,sllaw rebmahc eht deugalp noitpurroC
,mih ta ylnellus derats dlihc ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ecnagele reh ni eb ot detnaw ylno eH
tnemrag rehtael yrreblum a ni flow yarg wollas eht deredro
.ti rof dellac nus ehT
draug A .rewothctaw eht fo esab eht ta devirra
.foor eht sdrawot pu yaw rieht tperc ylwols dah semalf ehT
.desserac ti ecafrus yreve otni gnikaos thgilnoom
.derepsihw yllevarg eninac gniretsilb ehT ”.ecam ehT“
.noitseuq suoires A
.dnah ni ecam ,rebmahc eht fo tuo
.dnuorg ytsud eht no ecam eht gnicalp
”!sknar rieht nihtiw raeb ylzzirg a gnieb ereht rebmemer dluow I dna ,xoddaM eht htiw daerb nekorb ev’I“
,esroh sih morf llef nem rehto owt s’enisru eht fo eno sa
.eye na fo knilb a ni yks thgin eht revo derettalps
,denekrad yks eht sa
.yob eht htiw tcatnoc eye gnikaerb tuohtiW
.revihs mih edam dap wap s’yob eht fo gnileef yci
.ria dna dnuorg eht gnimusnoc ,rediw werg ezalb ehT
.nwad fo kaerb eht ta pu gnikaw
,deleenk nam ywenis ehT .wap sih ni ecam eht deciton eh nehw deifirtep erom neve saw eH
.dessentiw dah eh tahw gniwonk ton ,ezorf eH
,nwod saw flow eht dna
”?yob ,taht fo dnuos eht ekil uoY
.pets gnihsalc txen ehT
.tnereffid erew nem esehT
.lufraef erom werg mih gnidnuorrus nem eht
.tuons sih ta deppin sdniw digirf eht sa noom dna nus eht fo sterces eht nrael ot denraeY
.dlihc detaefed a fo thgis thguac
.deyarp dna elbissop sa drah sa seye sih tuhs ylkciuq yob gnuoy ehT
.seye eulb dna kcalb sih rednu tcelloc ot nageb sraeT
raeh llits dluoc yob eht tub
rewoT ehT ot setadpu dennalP
,syar dog gnitsalreve eht pu knird ylhsifles dluow ecarg reH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.reyarp sih deunitnoc eH
.si taht ,tpels eh fI
.edis rehto eht hguorht gnicafrus egde deniats-der ehT
.srae sih otni gniraoR
,mih ta daeh sih koohs dlihc ehT
”.etam ,ezalba flesruoy thgil annaw t’noD !won ereht ysae ,haoW“
.niaga revo dna revo elcyc emas ehT
,ecaf s’namsdraug eht dekcil semalF
.wollof I htap yreve dna
.rood eht fo staeb eht htiw gnola gnisluP .rehtona
.modeerf fo tmaerd dal gnuoy ehT
.osrot s’yob eht sa
.evoba srats eht gniteem dna
.noitseuq a yob eht deksa reve dah enoemos emit tsrif eht saw sihT
dna wap sih tuo dehcaer yob ehT
”.yob ,dnik ruoy derehctub roreuqnoC ehT“  .pets rehtonA
,regnessap a tub ma I
.llew sa reh rof yhtapmys gnileef morf mih pots t'ndluow taht
.trid eht ni gnikaos nosmirc eht no detaxiF
,dnuorg eht no sselefil yal taht flow eht sdrawot deppets dna tnuom sih ffo deppoh neht nam egral ehT .dewaffug eH
.taht yb tnaem nam eht tahw wenk reven eH
notyalC deirrac dna esor raeb ehT
.srats eht tuo derehtoms thgil dna ekoms eht sa derrulb yks thgin tnaidar ehT
.elgna thgir eht tsuj ta ti ta dehsal ti fi raor ot ti gnisuac
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.ecaf sih nopu ekorb elims a sa pu til ecaf siH
”?yob ,eman a htiw uoy desselb reve stnerap ruoY“
.erup raeppa tsomla dluow eh
.yaced sih fo mih dehsaw ehS
.mih otno taps erew taht esoht taeper dna secnetnes etalumroF
.gnirewsna erofeb hteet sih dettirg tar kcalb ehT
.ria eht ni noisnet eht esae ot deirt eH
.ssenkrad ni dlrow sih deteknalb retsis reh dna
”.evobA rehtaF ,uoy knaht I“    .ngis A
sih ni emit tsrif eht roF
,taorht sih ot decar traeh siH
.meht gnitirw yllautca naht seirots tuo gninnalp emit erom tib elttil a sdneps ohw retirw gniripsa na ,floW ynnaD yb
.ylesnemmi gnirevihs dna dekaN
.yrtnuoc eht decarg ehs reverehw gnola reh ynapmoccA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.devirra ymene eht erofeb rewot eht gnitaucave fo ksat eht su gnidnah ni emit on detsaw droL ruo os ,ereh yaw rieht gnihcram nees tsal erew yehT
,dnuora dekool yletarepsed dna llaw eht morf yawa flesmih dehsup
.dnoces a rof deppots traeh s’yob ehT
dna smra tnaig sih dexaler eh elihw
.mih ot rettam t’ndid tI
.sdniw eht etalucric ot srebme gnidneS
.pmub latnedicca eno nopu rettahs ot hguone eligarF
thgil fo kaerts eulb A .rehtona nehT
.eniN eht ot yarp ot woh mih thguaT .sdog eht tcepser ot woh mih thguat ohw nam ehT
”.si ti efloR notyalC“ .dekcuhc notgnihtrA  .cinut eulb sih morf tuo dekop tfut
.tsaf kniht ot dah eH
.ecam ehT   .rehtonA
.dehcuot reve dah eh gniht tsetfos eht saw ruf siH
.taeh gniredloms eht yb dezafnu ylgnimees
.htiw mih desselb dah sdoG eht sa thgim hcum sa htiw deyarP
.og tel ot gnitnaw reven ,ylevitcnitsni kcab raeb gib eht degguh eH
.yks eht ssorca tohs dah gnihtemoS
.mih otni ti denoegdulb nam degarne eht semit ynam woh rettam oN
.meht teerg ot ecnartne eht fo tuo tperc
.semalf eht morf dlogiram thgirb a denrut ruf siH
yarnoom fo remmilg A
deripsa yob eht ,yks eht ssorca yaw reh edam ehs sa tuB
.yllacitsacras deilper eH
hcihw ,erofeb ytuaeb hcus htiw derediorbme ratS a nees reven d’eH .sdog
,srehtorb em htiw ,uoy ekil tsuj ,yob a sa ereh emoc ot
ni devac doow eht sa
.tar derujni eno eht deksa eH ”?thgir lla uoY“
,noisiv s’yob gnuoy eht ssorca deppihw hsalf kciuq A   ”.niaga
.dnuorg eht no gnittoR
,elohpool eht otni thgir worra na tnes kcabesroh no nam driht ehT
.worra rehtona egrahcsid dluoc eh erofeb ti dniheb rehcra eht gnillik
”.ylefas esubsrehS fo ytic eht ot renosirp eht tropsnart ot soiakyL droL fo sredro rednu ereh era eW“
.dniheb mih gnivaeL
tub niks sih fo tcatnoc eht morf ton ,htmraw tlef yob eht ,efil
.prahs werg enot s’eninac eht nehw s'tahT ”.ela tsenif eht htiw nrevat a toG“ .derekcins eninac eht ”.ligis s’xoddaM esuoH s'tahT .rennab ruoY“
.nruter ot yks eht rof tpew eH
,yks eht ssorca ecnad reh edam noom eht litnu gnol t’nsaw tI
.ydob eht deugalp taht seilf eht htiw gnilgniM
.wap sih dessik ylkciuq yob ehT
dna kaolc eulb a dennod eH .rebmahc eht morf epacse fo snaem ylno eht dekcolb
.dleif eht ni llits gnidnats ,edistuo flesmih fo noisrev rehtona gnihctaw saw yob eht taht
,teiuq tpek eh ,kaeps ot deifirteP
,nekops dah eh retfa rof ,esruc a dna tfig A
nretnal tnaidar a gnidloh
.srehto eht htiw noillats sih no pu delddas notgnihtrA
.siht rof noitanalpxe rehto on saw ereht ;eb ot dah eH
.raew dluow sdraug eht leets dna rehtael fo eceip yreve
.mih fo thgis eht ta gniliaW
,uoy dnif I ,nevar yrevE
rethgirb enohs serifpmac fo sderdnuH
.htaenrednu hself dehcrocs eht gnilaever
.mih dehctaw tsuj yob ehT
.efloR notgnihtrA si eman yM“
deltit esihcnarf levon evisnetxe na htiw taht gnignahc no snalp eh ,tuB
,draug eht morf ekirts a deirrap ylkciuq dna drowsgnol sih werd raeb a fo niatnuom ehT
,sraey ynam retfa ,yllaniF
.noisnecsa sti edam nus eht litnu tiaw dna moor eht fo edis etisoppo eht no llaw eht ni eloh eht ta gnireep
.nretnal eht dedlew taht
tsehc s’notgnihtrA otni ecaf sih gniyruB
.sduolc eht dniheb rethgirb dna
.ti denigami eh ebyaM
.deireuq raeb nworb ehT
.degnol eH  floW ynnaD yb
s’ereht ;etal oot s’eH .trapa ekorb dna
,rewot eht fo srood nedlom eht morf tsrub
.saw rood eht erofeb tsrub ot tuoba saw daeh sih taht niatrec saw deyomaS gnuoy ehT
seye sih gninepo yllanif
yob ehT .elbuod eht did os dna
.suomrone saw eh ,raeb eht gniydutS
”.tsaE eht ni secrof leber eht gnihsurc ,deipucco oot raf si soiakyL droL“  ”-esoppus t’nod I .ereh tsaeb eht gnipeek ni tnevref yltsav saw soiakyL droL .dnammoc neddus siht fo su gnimrofni nevar on deviecer evah eW“ .desuap flow ehT
”.sdnal eseht nopu derehtag evah niwt reh dna
.evoba snevaeh yklim eht ylno gnivael
.sdrow tsrif sih kaeps ot elba saw eh ,esiW eht fo rewop eht hguorhT  .pets A
.nruter ot nus eht rof tpew eH   .tpew eH
erad uoY“ .drows sih gniward ,dekrab eh
”?eno ekil uoy dluoW“
,thgiew nwo rieht rednu delbmert sgel siH .deye-yraet
.yrc elttab sih gniyrc dna desiar drows
.mih ta gnihtemos gnituohs raeb ylrub eht eciton t’ndid eh ,thguoht ni tsoL
,renroc emas eht ni tis dluow eh oS
.maelg suoirolg reh ni mih ehtaB .mih mraW
.egap yrruFoS sih no erutuf raen eht ni elbaliava
.evila tuo ti ekam dna sriats eht nwod
.der denrut ecaf sih dna
.gniylper erofeb ylluferac dlihc eht deiduts enisru ehT    ”!no evom a teg ot deen ew ;seniv s’rewot eht otno hctac ot gninnigeb s’erif ehT“ .raef ni pmuj yob eht edam eciov elam a fo moob neddus ehT ”!ruhtrA“    ”?uoy t’nera ,deyomaS a er’uoY“
nopu gninepo s’tilsworra eht dnuora tcelloc tsorf ees semit ta neve dluow eH
.llafneve eht tuohguorht pu tpek gnieb fo noiton eht ot bmuccus dluow yob eht ,nageb taht ecnO
”?eno elttil ,sruoy s’tahW
retsum ot deganam eh
,mih fo tnorf ni wap rehto sih tuo dleh
.llaw nezorf eht ni kcarc eht dnoyeb ees ot ytiliba teews eht naht erom gnihton detnaw eH
.eci ot enots eht denrut yllaudarg hcihW
neht dna ,lluks sih tsniaga dednuop tsalb rehtonA
.dleif eulb dna revlis a no ,eulb strap ,revlis strap
.hgual ylleb a tuo tel dna tug sih deppals raeb ehT
”.reggib eb dluow uoy taht derugif I ,ereh dediser tsaeb a taht dias yeht nehw ,wonk uoY“
.tnelis deyats dlihc eht tuB
?mih ot desolcsid ylsuoiverp dah mar eht
.dlrow siht fo sterces eht revocsid ot ekat tsum I htap eht enihs em pleH“
.niaga nageb gnignol eht nehT
”?eman a evah ton uoy oD“
.yob llams eht dnuora smra sih depparw
.dlrow siht ni regnol oN
.rewot eht no pu yob eht gnivresbO
.snroH s’repaeR eht fo
.emit yreve gnidne eht dedaerd eh ,revewoH
.hself sih gnirutcnup ylhserf
.thgin eht gnirud tuo emac taht erutan fo secrof eht leper ot hguone kciht saw tlep sih ykcul saw eH
sesroh no nem eerht sa dehctaw eh ,ylsuoixnA
”!tirips eht s’tahT !eyA“
.dah eh ylimaf a ot gniht tsesolc eht erew yehT
,yriuqni eht retfa ecaf eht ot wolb a gnitcepxe flah saw eH
,hguohT .dnatsrednu ton dluoc eh ecrof tnelovelam A
.tnew yad rehtonA
.ediug ym era uoy dna
.reh htiw dnal eht levarT .reh wollof ot
dedaf ylkciuq htmraW
”!ti no ydaerla m’I ;part ruoy tuhS !eyA“
enin rieht tneserper ot stniop eniN
.tnemunom eht fo ecnartne nepo eht sdrawot klaw sih nageb neht niurb ehT
,rats detniop-enin A
.detuolf eH ”.tnuc ykculnU“
dna rehtruf ni denael raeb eht os
skaep deppac-wons eht revo dedaf ylkciuq dlog fo spord lanif s’nus eht sa htaerb peed a koot yob eht sa
.nem rehto sih ot kcab dekool dna drows sih dehtaehs ylzzirg ehT
.eb dluoc nem egnarts eseht ohw ot sa eulc a t’ndah yob ehT .esuap rehtonA
.semit fo sderdnuh ti nees d’eH
.nopu denworf raeb eht hcihw ot
.mih teerg dluow taht gnieb ylno eht ,noinapmoc sih saw ehS
.kcen sih ni deddebme reggad eht gniees
rorret ni dehctaw eH .ti saw sihT
”!retteb reve tlef I erehw yad a fo kniht tonnaC“
.sworra ymene diova ot revir eht dnuora gniylf tuohtiw evirra ot emit hguone dah evah ton dluow nevar A
sredluohs daorb siH
.regnessem ’O ,em raeH .rerednaW eht eb desselB“
.gnihton saw ereht tuB
ylzzirg eht derussA ".sworra
.niaga nus eht rof gnignol emas eht derahs htob yeht ebyaM
.noitcetorp fo level emos evig ot dna trofmoc rof flesmih gnigguh