,draob no ycavirp elttil saw erehT
.olah gnirettilg a htiw lessev eht gnidnuorrus
.sliat enin’o tac eht dekcilf etiL ed rD
,dnas gnilriws fo ssem a emaceb
.detseggus walcpiR
gnihtaerb reh dna ekorts reh dewols snikreP
.desoppus ehs ,aes eht otni hsarc d’yeht neht…neht dna
,retaw eht ni dednepsus ,walcpiR
,dehctaw snikreP sA
,su rof tnemssarrabme dna elbuort fo tol a esuac yllaitnetop nac etiL ed
.sevren noissim-tsrif morf ro ria delcycer eht morf rehtie ,yrd erew htoB
”.lla si noissim ehT
.moolg der eht ni nediw slipup reh tlef snikreP
.stekcajefil rieht ni detaolf werc eht
.enog gnol eb dluow enirambus ehT
.serbif dediarb fo htgnel a esopxe ot yawa dnas eht delbbarcs dna ,ti dnuof regiT
.ytip a hcus eb dluow taht tuB
.ebut-gnihtaerb eht dnuora dennirg dna ksam sih dniheb dekniw eh tub ,kaeps ton dluoc yehT .reh rof gnitiaw
.meht erofeb demool
.yawyna ti od lliw uoy fo tsom wonk ew tuB
,ytud evitca morf deriteR
,etihw tnew neercs ehT
,llef ti sa ti barg ot deirt ehS  .latem ton
.tac llams a neve yb dedda gard eht dna rood nepo eht yb retlik-ffo nworht yrotcejart sti
.dedulcnoc tac rehto eht
.sgniw eht level ot deganam ehs erofeb thgir dna tfel yldliw depoows enalp ehT
,rehtegot deb aes eht gnola demmiks stac owt ehT
,htuom ruobrah eht gnihcaorppa erew yeht taht decnuonna neris A
.gnifeirb eht no tnetni
.ecafrus eht ot tohs dna—
?meht kcatta eno siht dluow yhw tub ,suoiciv ylsuoiroton erew yehT !hsifdnuoH
meht evas ot tseb ruoy yrt uoy“
sih ot daeherof reh dehcuot dna dennirg snikreP
.niaga elbuort gnisuac trats ot elihw a mih ekat ll’ti
revoc sa dnas eht dettod taht skcor egral eht gnisu
esuom dna tac gniyalP
,doow eht ni skramwalc gnivael ,pu kcab flesreh dellup ehS
.hsif ekil kool ot tseb rieht gniod dna
.rae reh otni dias essuoM etalocohC
,essuoM etalocohC ot detniop snikreP
pohc etarak a htiw tuo tolip eht kconk d’ehS
a gniod ,snikreP thguoht ,ylno fI
,hctab reh ni tiurcer tsellams ehT
.ti rof mih etah neve t’ndluoc ehs ecin os dna
.erohs eht rof tuo kcurts ydaerla dah eh
I tub ,tsrif noissim eht tup ot desoppus saw I wonk I“
.seimene s’yrtnuoc ruo ot ecnegilletni terces pot gnissap si etiL ed taht
.nwod dna pu reh dekool eh sa nirg kciuq a snikreP evag essuoM etalocohC
,essuoM etalocohC ta dekool snikreP
.ezag s’ma’aM rednu rellams neve knarhs dna
.tib a no og did sgnifeirb reh tub
,ria eht otni dehcrul enalp eht sa no gnulc ehs ,gnimaerts dna tuhs seyE
.draob no gnineppah s’tahw rotinom nac ew os lluh eht no ecived gninetsil a tnalp essuoM etalocohC dna snikreP elihw
.ku.oc.reetyksuh ta
.meht dednuorrus taht ecnelupo eht ni ekat ot daeh sih detsiwt dna
,sreh tsniaga daeherof sih knob ot ssorca denael eH ”.KO eb ll’uoY“
.srotaderp rehto tcartta thgim doolb eht dna
:eviF-ytrihT locotorP gnitagitsni deredisnoc snikreP ”.emoC
,deb aes eht detagitsevni stac owt eht ,neercs eht nO
—dekram hctiws gib a saw ereht
,locotorp htorez eht s’tI
”,pu dessem I yrroS“
.sregnif owt devlovni
.sdrawyks ti delruh tlupatac eht sa tsuj tfarcria eht fo rood dnah-tfel eht rof gnarps snikreP
,noitamrofni pu kcip ot ytinutroppo fo ytnelp dah evah dluow eh erehw“
,ekirts ot lluh s’pihs a rof peed ooT
reh rednu sgel reh kcut ot emit ni tsuj
.ysmulc saw ehS .thgir s’tahT
,essuoM etalocohC ta dnuor dekool ehS
,snoitcennoc ssenisub dna lacitilop sih ot sknaht dnA
.nrets eht ni detnuom nug enihcambus resuaM a dna ,tlupatac a ni enalpaes llams a saw erehT .egdirb eht htiw kced eht gnitcennoc klawtac a dna swob eht morf gnidurtorp daehtac a htiw
.retto na sa denilmaerts sa saw ehs ,retaw eht ni ecnO
.aes gnitiaw eht sdrawot devideson
,daed era sdneirf ruoy llA .sselesu s’tI“
,enigne s’enalpaes eht morf ekoms etihw fo ffup a saw erehT
.meht evael ,elbuort ni steg yddub ruoy
”,tik ,em htiw kcitS“
.riahc a ni pu delruc ehS .dooG
.essuoM etalocohC ta debbats kaeb eht dna
.etiL ed rD ta derats ehS
,lessev sih fo sgnittif nedoow dna ssarb eht dna tniap etihw eht dehctam eH
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.daeh sih koohs anavaH eht ,wap rehto sih htiw mra sih gnipsalC
.kced no hctaw gnipeek enoemos saw ereht tnaem hsifdnuoh eht fo gnillik ehT
.flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer eb lliw hcihw
,euqapo ot denekrad knat hsif eht fo ssalg ehT
.noitcurtsni tnegru emos gnituohs
.ekatsim elbirret a neeb lla dah ti sselnU
.dias ma’aM ”,ecno ,maet doog a erew eW“  .deksa ehs
.deid ti sa gnihsarht
,)redluohs reh ssorca depard llits ,essuoM etalocohC ekil hcum(
ecaf depahs-egdew ,kcalb a ni derettilg seye erihppaS
wohemos ti pots dna enalpaes eht ot teg ot saw mia reH
.bus tegdim eht fo raer eht sdrawot reh denokceb ma’aM ”.drow A ?snikreP“
.rood eht desolc dna draob no snikreP dellup eH
detlep dna srae reh denettalf ehS
.naeco eht fo ssenkcalb eht otni hguorht maws dna rood retuo eht denepo taht leehw eht nups ehs
evisnopsernu dna hsigguls emaceb tfarcria reH
.flesreh fo etips ni dias snikreP ”,elbirret s’tahT“
”!pihselttab ruoy knaS“
,knird eht ni ffoyap sih dna enog pihs sih htiW
elggirw etarepsed eno ni tipkcoc eht dna tlebtaes reh morf flesreh detcartxe snikreP
,rehto hcae ta gnikool erew walcpiR dna eh yaw gums eht morF
.derednow snikreP ?sretsasid fo eugolatac A ”…saw taht“
,htgnel ni ertem doog a epahs lacirdnilyc a was snikreP
.essuoM etalocohC ta dekool snikreP
#   ”.snikreP ,hceeps fo erugiF“
”,hceeps fo erugif a tsuj s’tahT .hsif gib a s’eH
.kaet euqitna eht otno gnippird
.kcen sih fo kcab eht ta pohc etarak a demia ehs dna
.selbac rohcna ot dehcatta ,senim aes gnitaolf eht was ehs nehT
.ecnabrutsid eht rof esuac rehtona tuo kees naht rehtar ,hsif eht detcartta dah sthgil s’pihs eht taht emussa dluow yeht ,kcul htiW
,tuhs tsomla seye
,llaf eht morf delpmur won
.wodniw eht morf delley ehs
,eerf gel reh dekrej ehS .skcor owt neewteb kcarc a otni demmaj saw reppilf reh taht ees ot
.meht hguorht enohs nus gnisir eht erehw kced eht no thgil ynwat ro eulb ,der fo sehctap tsac rab devruc eht gnola degnarra selttob dna
.bus eht tixe ot tsal eht saw snikreP
.ssecca desirohtuanu tsniaga detcetorp eb ot lessev eht tcepxe dluohs uoy dna
.delaever eb reven dluoc hcihw fo sliated eht
.hctaw ot egdirb eht ot nruojda ll’eW“
,deliaf dah srehto nehw ti edam d’ehs tub
.raelc t’nsaw ehs ,taht dnoyeb—
”.uoy llet ot gniog m’I lla s’tahT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.lla retfa ,ereh saw ehS
.slangis citnarf ni devaw swap s’naV ehT
.rellams saw snikreP ,lleW .remmiws
.klawtac eht otno nwod deppord snikreP
.tuo detrulb snikreP
,swap tfel ruof gnivah rof desaet yltnatsnoc
”?taht tuoba wonk uoy od woH“
.retal ni smrof eht llif dna won rof ti htiw gnola og d’ehS
”.dedeen I trofmoc fo sdrow eht yltcaxE .tik ,sknahT“
”.emèrc al ed emèrc eht er’uoY“ .yltneg erom
”’.lla si noissim ehT
.smra reh ni essuoM etalocohC dna srae reh ni retaw
”,aera tegrat eht hcaer lliw ew ,setunim wef a nI“
”.emas eht od dluoc uoY“
,degadnab mra dna daeh sih ,essuoM etalocohC
.der peed erew liat yffulf yltnecifingam sih dna srae siH
)emit siht krow ot erus saw ti(
,gnol oot deregnil d’ehs reh dlot ekoms fo sffup dna dnuos gnippir A
,tac llams a saw flesreh snikreP
,knat a ni maws hsif laciporT
.elbac snoitacinummoc eht rof gnihcraes
.walc a htiw ti ta debbats dna
,swap reh ni tlebefil a
.detceted eb ecneserp ruoy tsum tnuocca on nO“
,ruobrah eht fo htuom ehT .htlaetS
,bus tegdim eht fo ecaps cillatem ,denifnoc eht nI
.seirots trohs fo rohtua gninniw-drawA ltoyóC dna rojaM asrU na reetyksuH
.reggib neve kool mih edam wohemos gninnur thgin rof desu thgil der mid ehT
.daed t’nsaw I tuB“
.kcits eht depsarg dna taes sih tsniaga kcab mih devohs ,ssorca denael snikreP
,essuoM etalocohC htiw eenk ot eenk saw snikreP taht depmarc os saw ti
eveileb ot nosaer sah ycnegA ecnegilletnI taC ehT
,ma’aM sulp ,werc owt
”.tespu eb thgim rewop dlrow fo ecnalab etaciled eht ,esiwrehtO
.gniog eb ot desoppus er’ew erehw s’taht ees nac I ,thguoht snikreP ,thgir lla ,seY
.kced eht ot ti dekconk ;ssalg reh rof dehcaer snikreP
,naV hsikruT a saw erianoillim evisulcer ehT
,evisolpxe eht fo thgiew eht fo deveiler ,sdrawpu dekcik enalp ehT
.TNIOPLAES yvaN a m’I
,enots kcils-deewaes fo sllaw htiw lennahc worran a
.rrup wol a ot eciov reh dna
.nottub a desserp dna etomer a pu dekcip
.aes krad eht ni demaelg ,rohcna ta gniyl ,thcayrepus eht fo lluh etihw ehT
.lwoy a htiw pu gnignirps dna edis eno ot gnillor
ffo nrot saw ksam yM“
nrut srae reh tlef snikreP ”.yrroS“
”!snikreP“ ”!ma’am sey ,ma’aM“
.maws eh nehw delggiw srae s’regiT yaw eht dna
.lennahc eht otni detniop
.sevaw eht fo tuo depael ti sa htorf fo duolc a ni deraeppasid dna sdrawpu tohs hsif gnol ehT  .desrepsid dna
,retsaf saw ,tnemele larutan sti ni gnivom ,hsif ehT
.suovren saw ehs nehw snup tac tuo werht syawla niarb esohw ,snikreP thguoht
#   ”!ni deggard tac eht tahw kool :dias I“
.ecived gninetsil eht ecalp ot tops a rof gnikool
,nwod epocsirep eht dellup ehS
.enalpaes eht no ti niart dna worp eht ni nug
.flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer ,reetyksuH yb
.wap a desiar dna tlupatac eht ta pu dekool eH
.gnihtyreve fo etips ni ,eugor dlo eht llik t’ndid uoy dalg m’I“
,pu uoy poocs dna pihs eht gnola wol ylf ot gninnalp saw I
,edis reh ta knird eht decalp eH
.essuoM etalocohC dennirg ”?yaw ym gnioG“
.sblub der eht rednu sdap reh sa knip sa dekool
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.izzucaj neknus lartnec a gnidnuorrus sregnuol dna sriahc htiw noitcurtsnoc ralucric a saw sihT
,decuder saw deeps gnimmiws reH
,epocsirep eht morf yawa gninrut
.thginot snoitacinummoc sih tpecretni ew taht lativ s’tI
s’tac rehto eht ot esolc daeh reh tpek esemaiS eht tub
.ti no nwod wap reh fo dap knip eht demmals ehS
,deraeppaer hsif ehT
lluh eht ot skcab rieht desserp stac owt ehT
,ylitsah dedda ehs
.ruf etihw gniwolf revo tius nenil etihw a gniraew
”.uoy ot txen tik eht kcehc enoyrevE !kcehc tiK“
.kced eht sdrawot delbmut lerrab a ekil dekool tahw dna
,oreh eurt a saw ehS
.ecafrus eht ekorb enirambus eht fo lluh eht neht
.edis rehto eht yB .deucser saw I
,hsaW tnemssarrabmE ehT :neetruoF locotorP rof dellac noitautis ehT
fI‘ ?ti t’nsi ,yaw TNIOPLAES eht s’taht tuB“
!sTNIOPLAES yvaN
.tnemom rehtona ni kcurts evah dluow ehs enim gnimool eht was ehs
,kced reppu eht dnuora deldis dna
,erehwyrevE gnivreS etile eht fo trap era ruof uoY“
.ti hguorht thgiarts gnikcits nooprah a
.drawrof depmuls eh dna ,lenap tnemurtsni eht kcurts elpmet siH
,ehpotsatac a rof tsylatac ehT
,dekcor enalp ehT
.eno egnaro s’regiT gnihcuot saw wapdnih nworb s’walcpiR taht deciton snikreP
.dehsurbelttob liat sih dna
.denialpxe regiT ”,noisolpxe eht fo ecrof eht debrosba retaw ehT“
,doow morf detcurtsnoc saw ,desilaer won snikreP ,hcihw ,lluh eht morf yawa llef tI .t’ndid ti ,oN .hO
,retaw eht tih enalpaes ehT
,delddap-god ehS
.ehtaerb ot drah ti edam tsehc reh ssorca ssenthgit sti dna
”.emitnaem eht ni od ot uoy rof ytnelp eb ll’ereht enigami I—yrrow t’nod tuB
.elzzum reh ot sreksihw reh gniretsalp dna
EGRAHC HTPED ESAELER
,lluf rebmahc eht
.oot ,retaw evoba evitceffe ytterp saw devlovni evisolpxe hgih eht ,tuo denrut ti sA
.meht evael ,elbuort ni steg yddub ruoy fi ,rebmemeR
.tfarcria thgil eht detlit dniw fo tsug a sa tsuj
.nrut htob meht edam retaw eht ni noitommoc A
.denetfos ezag erihppas ehT
.werc eht morf stuohs draeh ehs ,reh woleB
.semalf dna ekoms fo duolc a htaeneb dehsinav thcayrepus ehT
.denaom eh dna ,redluohs reh tsniaga decnuob daeh s’essuoM etalocohC
.ti ekorts ot nageb dna pal sih ssorca liat sih depard etiL ed
.mih dlot ehs ”,yako s’tI“
,kcab reh dehcra snikreP .giB kooL
cinap a ni nwod dekool ehS
.esac noissucnoc elbaborp a saw eh nevig ,yltneg—
,yawa delddap dna liat denrut ylkeem anavaH gib ehT
.reh ni gnihtemos nees evah tsum ma’aM os
,degrus sevaw ehT
.noissim txen eht dna emoh sdrawot ffo tes
.ruf reh tsniaga ylguns erom tas ti os tiustew reh fo ralloc eht gnitsujda ,desivda eh
.deneppah dah gnihton fi sa ssalg rieht dniheb gnimmiws
.noitcaer eht yb noitcerid etisoppo eht ni tnes saw ehs sa ,reh morf yawa tfird mih dehctaw ehS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
.enil eht no saw efil reh tub
.reh gninodnaba mih enigami t’ndluoc ehs dna rehtegot gniniart hguorht neeb dah yehT
”.denevretni I erofeb hsifdnuoh taht htiw dah uoy leud eht etiuQ“ .etiL ed derrup
.revo dna revo gninnips ,tfel ydob reh dellor ehS
”.uoy tfel ydaerla sah dneirf rehto ruoY“ ”!reveN“
”.ralucatceps etiuq eb dluohs noisolpxe ehT
.riapsed etanoitceffa fo erutseg a ni reh ta daeh sih koohs ohw
”.tfel tog ohw eno eht saw I esuaceb taht tuoba wonk I“
.dednim dah meht fo rehtien
.gniklat llits saw ma’aM .spoohW
:eerhT locotorP rof emiT
,gnihtyreve ta tnetepmoc ylgnitlover saw eH
.dedda eh ”!hsif ym evas dnA“
,reh rof pu ti kcip ot nwod tneb etiL ed ,yletiloP
,srae reh fo tuo ria eht ecrof ot gniwollawS
.egdub t’ndluow ti tub ,swaperof htob htiw reppilf eht no dellup dna retaw eht ni denrut
.aremac retawrednu na morf deef eht sa ti desingocer snikreP
,rehtegot tas maet eht fo tser eht erehw ot
.detceted gnieb tuohtiw esolc teg ot deedni xiS locotorP yrev eb ot evah dluow yehT
.reh rof ksir sseL
”,gnirats pots nac uoY“
.meht tsap dils llat saw snikreP naht regnol lee nA
.modeerf rieht yojne dluow hsif laciport sih depoh ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
mra sih morf sdrawpu dellarips ,retaw eht ni kni kcalb ekil ,doolb fo liart niht A
.htuom ruobrah eht otni ylsuoituac deson dna essuoM etalocohC tsap dehsurb ehS
.ruobrah eht fo sretaw llits eht otni dna
,reh knobdaeh ot denrut eh ,gninnirG
.tnew yeht sa dnas eht pu gnirrits ,yaw rieht fo tuo dekcilf hsif llams fo sloohcS
ti sekam eh fi—bus eht ot kcab steg eh nehw dnA“
,noitca fo tuo mra eno htiw esu on eb d’eH
.pu gnimoc saw nus eht won elbisiv
,neerg eno ,der eno ,sthgil noitagivan owt yb dekram saw ti retaw eht evobA
ro…enirambus yb kcatta tsniaga tnerreted a erew yeht
.retaw gnidleiy eht ta ylsselesu hctarcs dna swalc reh dnetxe reh edam liat reh no gut lufniap A
,sbolb egnaro erew werc eht ,reh woleB ”.siht tog ev’I“
.stipmra reh rednu swaperof reh dekcut ehs ,ylsuoicsnoc-fleS
”!og mih edam I !truh saw eH“
.selbbep eht gnoma deraeppasid dna debaes eht ot knas ecived gninetsil ehT
.snikreP si eman yM“
lennahc eht hguorht erew yeht nehT
.rubilacxE retawrednu na ekil kcor eht fo tuo dekop ti gnivael
.meht rof thgiarts gnidaeh ,niaga degrahc dna devrews hsifdnuoh ehT
.eson reh dekcil dna eugnot reh tuo dekop snikreP ”!ereh m’I .mU“
”,ruobrah eht deretne uoy tnemom eht morf ereht erew uoy fo lla wenk I“
.doow tcefrep eht ni deraeppa tned a dna
.erutaciduj ruo edistuo ,sretaw lanoitanretni ni er’eW
ecafrus eht ot esor ehs ,gniknilB
.snoom deruoloc ekil ecafrus eht no sloop edam dna syoub rieht no debbob taht
,reppilf eht fo eerf wapdnih tfel reh dekcik ehS
.swalc reh yb kced reppu eht fo egde devruc eht morf gnulc ehs dna ecaps otni nwod deppord sgel reH
.retaw fo llaw a gnisaeler ,derettahs ssalg ehT
.kcab reh fo llams eht ni wap a htiw gnola reh depleh essuoM etalocohC dna
.hsif yerp rellams a rof sdap knip dna ruf etihw eht nekatsim evah tsum eturb ehT
.kced eht fo level reppu eht ot etiL ed dewollof ehs ,ylkeeM
.tolip eht rewoprevo dna draob no kaens ot elba saw I taht enoyreve gnitcartsid fo boj doog a hcus did uoY“
,hteet fo lluf waj worran ,gnol a dna liat dekrof a htiw
regiT dna walcpiR
”?si sliat enin ’o tac
.yal ecafrus eht erehw reh dlot taht sthgil noitagivan eht fo snoom neerg dna der eht ylno saw ti dna
.deroom si thcayrepus s’etiL ed rotcoD erehw ruobrah etavirp eht ot ecnartne eht gnihcaorppa won era eW“ .meht dlot ma’aM
”.pu wolb uoy was
.etartenep ton dluoc bus eht erehw
:enirambus eht fo llaw renni eht gnola staes pmuj rieht ni tas dauqs TNIOPLAES eht fo tser ehT
.hcum os ton ,snikreP fo tser ehT
,retaw gnidaert saw essuoM etalocohC erehw dekram selbbub fo maerts A
”,boj eht did ti esoppus I tub
.llab a gnivah saw snup tac ni dellever taht niarb reh fo trap ehT
,taes regnessap rehtael der eht ni lwarps ot pal sih ssorca llef ehS
.retal ,essuoM etalocohC llet ot evah d’ehS
”.no gnitteg era sdneirf ruoy woh ees s’tel ,woN“
,ybbat lerekcam eht ,walcpiR
.enalp eht sdrawot
,ruf etihw dna yerg reh tsniaga delkcirp tiustew ehT
,lluh eht tsniaga ti decalp dna
,kcab pets a koot snikreP
.edis eno ot tac reggib eht dehsup dna sgel reh htiw tuo dekcik snikreP
.deman neeb dah tinu secrof laiceps eht mohw retfa esemaiS tnioplaes fo dauqs lanigiro eht fo eno saw ma’aM
.reh no nrut dna ti tceted dluow naV hsikruT eht
.liar eht revo detluav dna
,daeh reh revo gnihsaw
.regiT dna walcpiR
.slortnoc eht ta elbapac dna gnorts dekool swap nwo s’essuoM etalocohC
,kcits eht niaga gnisserp tsehc tac derruf-keels dna dellesihc fo sdnuop lareves htiw ,enalp ehT
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,dias ma’aM ”,snikreP ,lleW“
.ti no era uoy ton ro rehtehw ,emit s’ruoh eno ni evael lliw enirambus ehT
,hcuorc wol a ni gninnuR
”.won enif m’I .uoy knahT“
,ezalba llits saw hcihw fo hcum ,egakcerw gnitaolf eht gnomA
,moor fo ytnelp gniht eht evig ot thgirpu deppilf ehS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.gniniart rieht tuohguorht enod d’eh yaw eht
.tipkcoc eht otni flesreh deluah ehs
.dedda ehs ”,snikreP si eman ym dnA“
.noitacinummoc retawrednu raelc dna tfiws rof slangis wap fo metsys a depoleved dah dauqs TNIOPLAES ehT
.demra eb dluow werc eht ,esruoc fO
.kcen ot keehc morf gninnur racs gnol a htiw
.enirambus a yortsed nac ti lufrewop os erusserp fo evaw a gnitaerc
.taolG oT dnuorA kcitS reveN
.ti detneverp sutarappa gnihtaerb eht dna emit on saw ereht tub
,kced no gnithgil eht detcelfer yeht sa delkraps ti dnuora sevaw ehT
.detrats teg I ecno ,ecnahc eht rof em geb dna ,taht naht erom em llet ll’uoY“
.flesreh ot derettum ehs ”,yaY“  .yaw reh gnidaeh
#    .noissim tsrif reh pu dewercs d’ehS
.rehtegot ffo gnilddap
ti fo ecrof eht yb nwod dekconk saw snikreP
,reksihw ro rae na fo hctiwt lanoisacco eht rof tub llits tas
,liat s’walcpiR fo pit etihw eht desingocer snikreP tub ,derrulb erew serugif ehT
.swalc reh dednetxe dna ,srae reh denettalf
,gnirussaer erew ecnedifnoc dna ezis siH
”!ma’am ,seY“ ”!regiT“ ”!ma’aM“
”.enola lla era uoy ,eeweeP ,os dnA“  .enog erew
”.enalpaes ym morf egrahc htped a yb deyortsed eb ot ylnO
,ecneserp reh ni eb ot egelivirp a dna ruonoh na saw ti dna
I…taht tsuj s’tI“ .knip
.enirambus eht fo edisrednu eht ot reh thguorb taht nrut a otni definkkcaj ehS
.snikreP dellac ”?tahW“
”!evisnepxe erew yehT“
uoy rof daer dna nettirw
,edalamram eht ,regiT dna
.tceles ew tac fo erbilac eht s’taht esuaceB
,dael eht ni ,essuoM etalocohC
.meht etagitsevni ot pu maws ro edisa detrad rehtie sevlesmeht hsif ehT
,werc s’pihs eht fo eno yb reh morf nekat neeb dah sutarappa gnihtaerb dna tleb reH
,retawrednu etanoted ot dengised si egrahc htped A
.lluh eht edistuo taht htiw lauqe erusserp eht dna
:eniN-ytnewT locotorP dna resuaM eht htob gnittegrof
,ruobrah eht ni senim eb yam erehT“
:ruf sih fo nworb railimaf eht saw sa
”.did uoy esoppus I .ho...reven uoY ?uoY“
.knis ot nageb dna ,eciwt decnuob
.wapdnih erab reh ot detniop ohw
a tahw wonk uoy oD“
”.selkciP ,nur ot erehwon tog ev’uoY .eb lliw noos ro
,tnemom tsal eht ta wolb eht degdod etiL ed
.spil reh dekcil snikreP
,kced eht tsniaga dekcarc tI
”.swap nwo ruoy otni srettam koot uoy tub
,dniw eht yb hteet reh morf kcab dellup spil reH
,dias ma’aM ”,rebmemeR“
.flesreh dluow ehs ebyaM
.noissim eht gnisidrapoej dna efil nwo ruoy gniregnadne naem dluow ti nehw yddub ruoy retfa kool ot uoy redro t’nac eW“
,pu saw yaw hcihw llet t’ndluoc snikreP retaw krad eht nI
.demoob dna gnar lwoy esemaiS s’ma’aM
,naramatac lluh-niwt a saw thcayrepus ehT
”!essuoM etalocohC“
.pu revoc ot dah netfo d’eh hcihw
”.ot elba ton er’uoy dna
,evom a edam ehs fi taht erus saw snikreP tub
.tuo tuc dna
,tiustew reh morf dedurtorp taht snikreP fo snoitrop ylno eht ,swap etihw ruoF
”locotorP htoreZ ehT“ saw sihT
,taps ehs ”,snikreP s’tI“
,debaes eht ni elbac citpo erbif etavirp s’etiL ed ot pateriw a tcennoc lliw regiT dna walcpiR“
.gnorw erew AIC eht dna ma’aM taht epoh tniaf eht ot gnulc snikreP
,essuoM etalocohC ton ylniatreC
,mra sih ni dnuow eht revo gnisserd dleif a deppals d’eH
,stnemurtsni eht fo nacs tac
.yawateg s’enirambus eht naht tnatropmi ssel saw epacse nwo reH
.epahs otni dekcil d’ehs stiurcer eht gniynapmocca no detsisni syawla ehs
.noitisop otni ti dekcol esab citengam sti erehw
”,elbatrofmoc flesruoy ekaM“
.ruf sih hsurb ot emit dah wohemos d’eh fi sa dekool ti dna
.knat hsif eht tsniaga llef dna ,delbmuts
.kcolc tipkcoc eht ta decnalg ehS
daeh s’snikreP fo pot eht revo dekool ma’aM ”.enif did uoY“ “—
.noissim tsrif reh pu wercs ton dluow ehS .emit elttil a dah llits ehS
,snikreP rof ,tub ,dnuos on dah mlif ehT
.noitom wols ni deneppah tnemevom eht ,retawrednU
.mih nioj ot ssorca maws dna tleb reh morf srettuc eriw eht dellup
”.ytitnedi wen a dliub ot hguone
.lessev eht fo edis eht tsniaga knat negyxo reh dekconk dna ti delbmuf
:xiS locotorP TNIOPLAES saw tahT
.reh dleh dna thguac maeb eht sa eralg gnidnilb sti rednu stils ot knirhs slipup reh leef dluoc ehs erus saw snikreP
.noitagitsevni rednu si eh tuo sdnif eh fi
.ti dnif dna nwod evid d’ehS .eniF
.elbac dehcuot srettuc tnemom eht trapa erutcip eht deppir taht noisolpxe eht raeh dluoc ehs fi sa saw ti
.xelfer no dednapxe slipup fo stes ruof sa
.etiL ed dna reh neewteb knat hsif eht fo ssalg nekorb eht gnipeek
tleb dethgiew reh no hcuop eht morf ecived gninetsil eht werdhtiw snikreP
,pu gnirevoc emos ekat ot gniog s’ti dna ,od ot dlot erew uoy tahw etiuq toN“
seye egnaro sih deknilb eH
,retaw eht ni deraeppa detniop dna kcalb gnihtemos dna
.selbac depmalc fo eldarc s’tac eht gnoma
.nips ot nageb relleporp eht dna
,nwod kcab dehsarc ti ,retal stnemoM
,noissim suoregnad a si siht taht uoy dnimer ot deen t’nod I
!maeT lanoitaN ,ecI nO spahreP ,dnaL ,riA
.stiustac egnaro ni desserd seiggom gnikool-hguot fo noitcelloc a
.nruter lliw uoy fo lla ton elbissop s’ti dna
,regiT dna walcpiR tuo ekam tsuj dluoc ehS
.kaeb sti fo baj eht diova dna
,ssenismulc reh nevigrof syawla dna yaw eht fo pets yreve reh htiw neeb d’ohw
.stsirw reh htob dnuora desolc wap nworb A
”locotorP htoreZ ehT“:yojne esaelP
.daeh reh evoba swaperof reh desiar dna
.lortnoc ni kcab mih evah ot feiler a saw tI
.efil otni dezalb thgiltops A …ehS
.yaw rednu tog noissim eht ecno yltnereffid devaheb elpoep ebyaM
.retaw krad eht otni gniraeppasid
,elttil a truh ot ti rof hguone drah tsuj
krow reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
,etiL ed rotcoD fo ngis on saw erehT
.afos rehtael dlo na ro sragic ekil ,kool enilucsam ,evisnepxe na dah ti
,ecalpkroW eht ni tnemssaraH lauxeS htiw gnilaeD
elbat eht ssorca trahc lacituan a daerps eH
.reh fo tuo htaerb eht dekconk ffoekat ehT
.uoy tuohtiw tesnus eht otni ffo lias lliw draoba esle enoyreve dna eh—
,ma’aM saw ereht dna ,nepo deppop hctah ehT
.eceipeye eht hguorht dekeep dna ecalp s’ma’aM koot snikreP
.gniliec dednuor eht dehsurb ylraen srae esohw nworB anavaH eguh eht
.eno doog a saw tahT
”!walcpiR“   reetyksuH yb
,deunitnoc esemaiS eht ”,ecnerefnoc a morf yadot thcay sih ot tuo welf rotcoD ehT“
”!1D ,1C ,1B ,1A“  .noisolpxe eht fo taeh eht leef dluoc snikreP dna
,did ehs fi taht desilaer snikreP .etiL ed dereffo
.mih htiw setonknab ni yenom fo mus egral a thguorb eh taht nwonk si ti dna
,rewot gninnoc eht tsriF ”.skrahS“
.serehps dekips eht neewteb htap a gnireets
.meht evael reven dluow ehs tub ,reh evael thgim seiddub reH .oN
.kcilf deifsitas a evag liat reh dna
?oot ,sevren taht saw rO
,reetyksuH ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb
”!ti hcnuaL !enalpaes eht hcnuaL“
”?yddub s’etiL ed .rD uoy ereW .m’aM“
.erutcip eht otni maws sepahs owT
,derevoc saw daeh reh litnu gnisir dna sreppilf ylniagnu rieht ni swapdnih reh gnillihc
,snoitarepo trevoc sseltnuoc tuo deirrac dah ehS
daeh reh tsniaga srae s’tac elttil eht gninettalf retaw eht ,debaes eht gnola devom yehT
,nworB anavaH eht ta ecnayonna reh tips ot dnuor dekool ehs sA
.lewot eht ni gniworht ekil tlef ehs nehw gniniart eht hguorht reh dexaoc dna deillub dah ohw ,ma’aM toN
essuoM etalocohC evag snikreP eno ehT
.ertnec eht ni deraeppa erutcip yzzuf a dna
.stohs elbirret eb lla d’yeht ,esruoc fo dnA
.enirambus eht ,dnoyeb ,dna ,yal htuom ruobrah eht hcihw ni noitcerid eht ot neht
.edolpxe dluow enim eht dna nroh a fo pit eht htiw tcatnoc tsethgils ehT
,tius nenil etihw eht rednu deltsirb ruf siH
sTNIOPLAES fo ograc sti htiw enirambus eht dna
,retaw dloc htiw yllaudarg dellif rebmahc kcolria ehT
.reh dnuora deppolf hsif sa doow tew eht ssorca gnidils flesreh dnuof dna
,nwod dna pu dna edis ot edis morf devom ehS
”!duorp em od ll’uoy wonk I dnA
,dedda ehs ”,semitemoS“
.gnihsif sdrawot edutitta gnitropsnu ylknarf a dna smrofinu rof gniht a fo tib a htiw erianoillim yranidro yltcefrep a fo thcayrepus eht eb dluoc sihT
,liatkcoc a dexim eh sa reh ot kcab sih htiw doots etiL ed
.ecafrus eht no selbbub yawaevig on eb dluow ereht os
,yal dnal noitcerid hcihw ni erus yleritne t’nsaw ehS
,lessev eht fo kced dehsilop eht no doots snikreP
.uoy ekil yttik elttil ytterP
”.kcab yaw eht lla gnihtaerb yddub od ot dah ew os
.gel reh ta llup gnihtemos tlef dna
,etiL ed delley ”!reh retfA“
.noissimbus otni ti dekorts eh dna ,dehsal liat siH
,edisgnola desiurc dna lluh s’pihs eht fo evruc eht dehcaer yehT
.deunitnoc ma’aM ”,noituac emertxe esicrexE“
enihcam a pu tes ot dekrow meht fo eerht
,sremmiws gnorts era snaV hsikruT ecnis ,taht detcepsus snikreP dna
secapS thgiT fO tuO gnitteG :eviF locotorP—
;meht evig dluoc I noitamrofni eht rof llew em diap yehT
.dehctiwt pit ehT
”.enirambus ruoy knaS .5C ,4C“
.slortnoc eht no deluah ehs drah woh rettam on draobrats ot dna nwod gnitfird
.did ehs fi neve ti ekam t’ndluow ehs erus ytterp saw ehs dna
.snoihsuc klis eht no hctap tew a evael dluow ehs
”locotorP htoreZ ehT“
,ruof fo maet odnammoc a htiW
.kaeps ot dekcohs oot
.kced eht dessorc ti sa wodahs s’tfarcria eht morf gninnur
,deb aes eht ot knis hsif eht dehctaw dna
.tiusrup ni kced eht ssorca deddiks eh sa retaw fo yarps a pu gnidnes
.kcen reh no racs eht deregnif ma’aM  ”.lliw uoy fi
.elzzum reh tsap denihw gnihtemoS
tnemnrevog eht dna AIC eht