,desiar waperof eno htiw ,weiv edis eht
,tellaw sih tuo werd eH
.yek potpal a ta yltnahpmuirt deppat oeL
.eno tsal eht ta mih dellac dah veL ,’noil
na saw sucigleB oeL
”?daoR rodarbaL ot teg ot woh wonk uoy oD“
.ysae t’nsaw ti tub ,ega nredom siht ot ni tif ot dedeen eH
,oot ,sgniht rehto erew erehT
ytic eht fo nalp a pu thguorb ehs
.noitcerid eht fo erus etiuq t’nsaw eh
,tnapmar noil a delbmeser tahwemos taht epahs a demrof
,ylihtoot ,delims oeL
?’tnaveler‘ ,naem uoy od tahW
.gnilddip yob llams a fo eutats a ot tuo tsol d’eh ,tnorf esidnahcrem eht nO
.ereht sriah evitisnes eht gnilkcit draeb reh
”?meht fo eno eb t’now siht wonk uoy od woH“ .dias eh
,deltrats ,oeL ”.yawa
”?ereh no em wohs uoy naC“
,deilper oeL ”,tniop yM“
,lanoitanretnI snoiL er’eW
”,egnahc fo diarfa neeb lla ev’eW“
,erutplucs cilbup fo eceip detcelgen emos ekil dekool eh woN
”.noos uoy ot klat ,lleW“
,sdnomaid dna dlog ni detsevni d’eh ykcul saw tI
,ecnassianeR eht ni neeb dah ti sa
.won ylkciuq os degnahc snoihsaF
,erauqs eht ssorcA
”.ssob ruoy llet t’now I“ ”.siht tpecca t’nac I tub
.dnim t’ndid eh dnuof oeL tub
,spam sih no semanecalp tneicna eht ekiL
.gnisworb luferac dna esolc dedrawer yeht tub ,segalliv dna srevir eht
sdaeh detlit eht yb llet dluoc oeL
.sreganeet derob yb no delbbircs dna deppihc
,yrdlareh fo dlrow deiferar eht ni nevE
.tnemucod wen a detaerc dna nepo telbat sih deppilf eH
,snoil delbmessa eht ssorca derednaw ezag sih sA
.taht fo trap er’ew—
essenoyL ”?’dnert nO‘ ?’ygdE‘
,detad ylsselepoh saw ti ydaerlA
.ylfeirb ,yaw sih dekool raeb yddet a gnidloh lrig A
.thgil tseb rieht ni detneserp eb ot devresed seot sih neewteb stelmah redrob eht dna
.erutuf ni ylhguoroht erom moorg ot devloser dna
ni deraeppa yllanigiro yrots ehT
.sniatnuof fo hsalps gnihtoos sti htiw
.siht naht esrow hguorht emoc ev’eW
.stnemhserfer eht rof daeh dna elgnim ot gninnigeb
,noitasrevnoc rof yb-sressap deppots eh won
,yllis eb ot tuo snrut yrt ew gnihtemos fi rettam t’nseod ti taht si“
.hguoht ,thgir er’yehT“
”?ppa spam a deen I dluow yhW ?ppa spam A“
”,sedaced wef a ni ecalp fo tuo ylsuoedih eb nac yadot looc skool taht gnihtemos wonk lla eW“
.neercs eht no pu dehsalf LRU ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
:deraeppa sucigleB oeL fo tiartrop railimaf eht
.yrotsih rieht fo meht gnidnimer yb yrtnuoc rieht ni edirp s’elpoep sih eldnik ot saw esoprup s’oeL
;oeL htiw enif saw hcihw ,elbaliava sa gniwohs saw modgniK detinU eht fo noil elbarenev eht ylnO
.selcsum sih htiw delppir taht soottat
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
.yldas ,deilppus oeL
.eno ykni sih tsniaga eson knip ,mraw reh dehcuot dna redluohs sih no wap a tup ehs ,essenoyL tsap yaw sih edam oeL sA
.em desingocer uoy tuB“
,muigleB otni sremocwen emoclew ot
esoht…esoht ot noitnetta on yaP
.yromem rieht morf gnidaf saw eh
.tuo doots nalp nwot eht os pecib a dexelf eH
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna tenalPruF morf
.dneffo ot ton gniyrt ,deksa eh
.ereht revo gninrom ecin a ekil skooL .BL ,olluH“
.tnemssarrabme fo duolc a ni dniheb tfel ,skcart eht otno polfylleb uoy dna ,ssiM
yletinifed lliw ereht dnA
”!esruoc pihsnezitic eht fo trap er’uoY“ ”?taht s’woH
nwot eht fo noitcurtsnocer a ees dluoc ecneidua sih dna oeL os ,weiv eht degnahc nottub A
.tuo gnillol eugnot der ,gnol a dna ,hgih daeh
.slessurB ni riaF s’dlroW 8591 eht rof tliub erutplucs latem eguh eht
.stelmah gniruobhgien neewteb spag eht gninediw
!elpoep sih fo tirips duorp eht detneserper eH
?oeL rof emit dah ydobon taht rednow yna ti saw
.oot ,noitan sih yllar dluow eh dna snoil eht deillar dah eH
.dekool ehs derit dna dlo woh deciton
edaf…tsuj dluohs ew ebyam
.seitlayor eviecer t’ndid eh os ,thgirypoc fo tuo gnol saw egami sih dna
”.senamkcen retspih
.hsuh eht otni ,dias eh
sepahs elpmis ,dlob ni serutaerc lanoitan rehto elihW
.tseuqer tahc etavirp a tnes eH
.meht ot lobmys a gnieb fo noitasnes eht saw
eb ot demees gnileef lareneg ehT
.par otni yarof sih tegrof mih tel reven dah
,niaga tellaw sih ni gnihcaeR .kcab delims eH
.sselehtenon elbasingocer yltnatsni tub ,noil depahs-ynnuf A !noil a saw eH
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.enil txen sih deredisnoc eh
.enohp sih gnisu tsuj ,yrtnuoc sih ni no gniog s’tahw em wohs nac veL
.no devom sedaced eht sa dniheb tfel
”,ti esu nac snairotsiH“
.seye sih desiar oeL
,sucigleB oeL edisni erehwemoS
trohs ylevitaler a revo degnahc dna deppohc yrotirret sih nees dah veL nevE
”?ppa spam a evah uoy t’noD
.emoh daeh ot emit saw ti ebyaM
.niart ratsoruE a ekil gnola dehsur tsiegtiez ehT
.ylluftcepser seye sih deworran oeL
,niks sih deppam taht sliated enif eht fo duorp saw eH
,doots setageled rehto ehT
,thgiew gnisol eb dluohs eh ,gnihtyna fI
.golb ym sdaer ydoboN
.oeL ,taht naht retteb er’uoY“
.noitacol rieht dekram taht bolb der eht no ni demooz dna
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.evaw lager a ni wap sih desiar dna
,denraw essenoyL ”,veL“
”.alletuN dna maerc htiw elffaw eno dna ettal enO .sucigleB rM ,og uoy erehT“   reetyksuH yb
!esnesnoN“ .dias eh
.yek eht saw taht ,ecnaveleR
egats eht tfel eH
,muigleB fo elpoep eht ot dnA
.sliat owt sih gnihsiws ,dedisbus noil hcezC eht dna
tnegra fo ruf rieht htiw
,yas sdneirf enilno nehW
”.dnarb gnidael eht neve t’nsaw tI“
,erutuf eht tuoba thgir saw eh depoh eH
.selffaw eht no nwod tuc ylbaborp dluohs eH
.tsae eht ot erehwemos morf tnecca thgils a htiw hsimelF ekops ehS
.elffaw sih fo etib a koot
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,tsap eht ni ,enil pukcip doog a neeb dah tahT
.tnaw I revenehw ,tahc a rof uoy fo yna fo dloh teg nac I !NOIL
.seirots trohs fo rohtua gninniw-drawA ltoyóC dna rojaM asrU na
”.sdnats llits tniop eht tuB“ .noil regnuoy eht dias ”,msinummoC fo gnikniht saw I ,yllautcA“
”?dnab pophtnys eht xeleT rO ?gniht eht xeleT“
”,yllis kool ot tnaw t’nod tsuj I“
.tsap ruoy rebmemeR .evarb eB
.hceeps sih rof saw emos taht tnedifnoc saw eh
.seirutnec eht hguorht htrof dna kcab pam eht devom rabllorcs a dna
,uoy knahT“
,rof thgif dna dnuor yllar ot gnihtemos dedivorp dah eh ,ecno ,sA
repaP‘ .tpmetnoc nepo htiw mih detaert ydaerla ,aihcezC fo noil revlis eht ,sliaT-owT veL ekil soryt gnuoY
.yrtnuoc wen rieht tuoba nrael nac yeht ,stnargimmi eht ,ni gnimoc elpoep wen eht dnA
.der hsulf seirotirret sih tlef eH
.ti ecneulfni dna yrt ot ecalp sih t’nsaw ti tub
.syad lainoloc dab eht morf
”?thgir lla uoy erA
saw yregami noituloser hgiH
”!erehT“ .telbat sih fo neercs eht ta deppat dna
”?wonk uoy ,tnaveler s’taht yas ot gnihtemos gnidnif emit drah a gnivah m’I
?raeh meht fo yna dluow tuB .tuo ti raor dna
.devaw muigleB dna UE eht fo sgalf eht ,meht evobA
noitaN a fo lobmyS
.nwonknu lautriv a
;essenoyL ta ylreporp dekool
!ereh thgir gnittis si ytitnedi ruoy fo trap tuB
,mra na tuo dehcterts eH
,)giw a ni tac dlog ,egral a saw noil a taht aedi eugav a htiw detniap meht fo tsom dna
.secnaraeppa pu peek ot tsuj ,troffe siht llA
!ecneidua sti ni noissap hcus esuora eutats gnissip a ees ot ekil d’eH
.esualppa suoiruf ot
.mih no nwod kool ot demees lla yeht yhw saw taht ebyaM
”.gniyrt peek ew sa gnol sa
.noisivelet lanoitan no par a mrofrep ot oeL tog dah reciffo RP sih ,seiteniN eht nI
,eson sih morf maerc gnikciL
.noitaicerppa fo sesion etilop edam
,swap noil rof esicerp dna
.oot ,loohcs ni nerdlihC
ytiroines dna ytingid reh tub
.ssem a saw eh ,rafa morF
;hguone neeb dah steerts eht hguorht yllager gniklats tsuj ,ecnO
.elpoep nwo sih neve
.tneserp ta tuo deglub ymmut sih yaw eht rof esucxe on saw ereht tub
,yltnangidni deggurhs eH
.staert naeporuE fo reilppus a tub gnihton saw ,seirtnuoC woL eht fo noiL eht ,sucigleB oeL ,sreep sih ot :saw ti erehT
,sraey wef a ni dnA
seirutnec lareves rof doog saw eltsac a ,tsap semiT
.demahsa eb dluohs eh hcihw fo secidujerp dna stseuqnoc suoibud fo lluf saw tsap eht taht ro ,yffuts dna gnirob saw yrotsih taht draeh rehtie eh
,sdneirf dah eh sa rafosni
”!emoh teg uoy nehw yrt a ti eviG
,elbat eht ot tsap eht thguorb tsuj eH
,HCEEPS ETONYEK :ECNEREFNOC LANOITANRETNI SNOIL
,essenoyL htiw pu gnirb t’ndid uoy stcejbus niatrec erew erehT
,meht pleh t’nac ew dna ,erom yna su deen t’nod yeht fI
,snihc yreksihw ro ruf dlo-seirutnec ot dnik ton
.pam eht ffo gniog ,won gnilytseerf saw eH ”?rebmemer
.gnileef ydaeh a saw tI
.erofeb reh nees reven dah eh fi sa
.yromem cilbup morf dedaf seman rieht sa gnirrulb erew mih dellebal taht snwot dna setats ehT
.uoy rebmemer I tub ,denrael I tahw fo tol a nettogrof ev’I“ .delims ehS
;hguoht ,deugirtni erew yehT
.dellac erew yeht revetahw ro
,elbidercni saw tI
.enirugif citsalp a sa ro ,sdractsop no elbaliava t’nsaw eH
.ecaf nedlog dna evarg railimaf eht gniwohs
.taoc sih dettops taht sdrow dedaf eht no deyalp dna
,daeh sih evoba neercs eht nO
.degnahc dah pam sih yaw eht
?elbativeni eht gniyaled tsuj taht t’nsI“
.lausu sa senohp elibom rieht ni pu depparw llA
.muidop eht sdrawot denrut srae eht dna
,ereht liat sih morf knuhc a nekat ,ereh rae na dekcin dah seitaert dna sraW
”.xelet sa tniauq sa tsuj dnuos lliw siht lla
.su tcejer ll’yeht yrrow ew dna ,egnahc elpoep ruo dna egnahc seirtnuoc ruO“ .meht dlot oeL
.erutuf eht detnaw tsuj yeht ;erom yna tsap eht tuoba derac ydoboN
.daeh reh koohs tsuj ssertiaw eht tub
reverehw ro ,aihcezC ro ,muigleB ni gnivil ekil ti s’tahw ,yeh
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.koob a ni kcuts saw eh ,sgalf ’seirtnuoc rieht no tfola desiar erew
ta kooL !su ta kool tuB“
,syad eseht mih desingocer enoyreve toN
,eros dna dloc ediskcab sih gnikam yltnerruc saw taht riahc éfac leets
,swap sih daerps eH
sredrob eht ot stisiv siH
”,gniog er’ew erehw sgalf eb ton thgim erehT“
.ti tuoba deirrow tib a m’I ,yllautcA .eisseN ,gninroM“
.emoh fo meht dnimer taht sgniht deen yeht
.ssertiaw eht denokceb eH
.gnimmargorp fo staef wen ot no maet spam eht derrups mrof dna epahs yrev sih os
dna reggib mrof yehT
etacirtni oot serutseg fo seires a htiW
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,reetyksuH yb
,lamina lanoitan a sA
.emoclew ssel erew
,yenom s’yadot ni sselhtrow ti gniredner ,drail eht dna cnarf eht htob detaderp
slipup sih knarhs thgilnus gninrom ehT
.ecnayonna htiw dehctiwt ,elbat eht rednu neesnu ,liat sih hguoht
.deraeppa nalp teerts a
”?oot ,snoitativni rennid ruoy gnirongi llits torioP dna nitniT .em raeD“
.eson sih fo tnorf ni dnah a devaw ehS
,hcuot reh ta deltsur eH
.elbat eht fo ecafrus latem eht ni flesmih denimaxe oeL .huH
,daeha thgiarts derats
.erom yna su deen t’now yeht taht deracs teg ew dna ,snoinu dna secnailla wen ekam yehT
.noissefnoc gninmad tsom sih edam dna ,deplug eH
.yppahnu dna deracs erew yeht
,NOIL ot ni deggol dna nwod swen eht desolc eH
,pecib nwo sih fo noitatneserper lacihparg a ni dessorgne gnol oot rehtar tneps dah eh taht erawA
”seirtnuoC woL eht fo noiL ehT“ saw sihT
.deppots dna deretlaf esion eht ,ni denioj esle ydobon nehw tub ,palc ot nageb ,essenoyL ylbaborp ,enoemoS
noil hsitirB dlo eht ta dekool eh
,smret nwo rieht no yrtnuoc eht otni sgniht wen democlew yeht elihw taht saw ,derehtag eh ,weiv gniliaverp ehT
.senildaeh eht desworb dna deefswen sih ot dehctiws eH
nwot hcae fo gnilledom eht htiw meht depleh dah eH
ecnayonna sih ot tub ,ereh dnuora erehwemos pots mart a saw erehT
.sepirts dna sratS
.enam sih morf sknah deppir dna sedis sih derracs
.elbaruovaf saw etar eht revenehw detrevnoc eh hcihw
.ni tif dna nrael meht pleh ot tpoda ni emoc ohw seno wen eht taht sgniht yrev ehT .sgalF
.ytitnedi lanoitan eht etulid dluow yeht dna
.stsimertxe lacitiloP
.ereht neeb dah eh ,lla retfa
.tsirw sih fo edisni derettelnu eht no htmraw eht leef ot revo ti denrut dna ,dednetxe swalc
,ecreif kool ot desoppus saw eH
.dedlareh ti tahw derednow dna
,sremmargorp eht htiw gnikrow ,nuf neeb dah tI
gninrom taht emit dnoces eht rof dna
.elgna yreve morf oeL gninnacs dna
.nrob neeb dah lobmys a dna
”?gniog etonyek eht s’woH
”.sdnomaid evah uoy yhw sseug nac I
”seirtnuoC woL eht fo noiL ehT“:yojne esaelP
,detsixe nwonk t’ndah eh flesmih fo strap nees d’eH
;oot ,sega eht hguorht
.rewop ot esor snoitan rehto sa seirutnec eht revo eldniwd eripme reh nees dah noiL hsitirB eht ,oeL ekiL
,railimaf yltaerg erew segA kraD eht ni stsitra hcihw htiw tpecnoc a t’nsaw msihpromid lauxes(
!ecreif dna elbon saw eH
.yrotsih ni tuoba gnippiks siht
,hguoht ,oeL deticxe yllaer dah tahW
.orter saw ti esuaceb KO wohemos saw taht tub
.dekrims essenoyL fo ecaf neercsno ehT
.skoob cimoC .dooF
.erauqs eht gnissorc elpoep eht delliw eh ,gnorts eB
”.nwod denrut tog dna ecuas pihc fo dnarb a rosnops ot deilppa I
.eno tseb sih saw noiL hsitirB eht
,yrotirret rieht otni peerc srats dlog sti htiw galf eulb eht dehctaw dah ,mih ekil ,meht fo ynaM .napsefil
,stiucsib fo tcepsorp eht ta neeb evah thgim ti fo emos hguoht nevE
,edis yknuhc dna trohs eht no neeb syawla dah oeL
ystra eht fo taes eht no pu pmuj ot detnaw eH
,ekoj dlo eht fo tnemegdelwonkca deddon oeL
,muimotA eht ni flesmih dehsilbatse dah oeL ,oga sedaced emoS
gnihpargotohp skeew
.aremac reh detniop tsiruot a
.tsehc sih ssorca serutaef lacihpargoeg dna snwot eht gniyalpsid
tneps dah ynapmoc erawtfos eht morf maet ehT
.stib dab eht egdelwonkca dna stib doog eht rebmemer ot elpoep sih rof
.ecaep ni hceeps diputs sih no kroW
.raey sih fo thgilhgih a eb ot desu ecnerefnoc ehT
.BL ,uoy ni htiaf evah I“
.napaJ dna ASU eht morf snootrac dna cisuM
”.yldneirf os dekool ecaf ruoY
,slexip ni mih gniredner fo segnellahc eht yb deugirtni yltsom erew yeht fi neve ,noitnetta rieht dloh ot gnirettalf dna
.ezag sih deppord oeL
.ti gnidaerd saw eh ,woN
.krowteN enilnO lanoitanretnI snoiL eht
.enoyreve rof nuf s’ti tuB
”.slefawpoorts eb
etats eht yb detnarg neeb dah oeL dnepits ehT
,netfo erom dna eroM
.nosrepselas gnizalg elbuod ro citanaf suoigiler emos ekil
”.niaga pam eht no muigleB tup ot gniog si hceeps ruoy wonk I
etats eht morf yenom ekat dna sboj esufer ro ,sboj eht lla ekat dluow yehT
seirtnuoC woL neht eht fo
.dnomaid dezis-dim a tuo dekcip eh
”,BL ,hceeps tnellecxE“
erauqs delbboc eht ssorca tuo gnirats
.secalp eseht fo yna esingocer t’nod I“
”!aH ?spam era uoy esuaceB .regit repap a ekil ,wonk uoY“
.won rof flesmih ot gnipeek saw eh taht
,seirtnuoc rehto ot esrepsid elpoep ruo nehW“
.drawno degnulp oeL
.snoil eb lliw ereht tuB .snoitan ro ,sredrob eb ton thgim erehT“ .dias eh
,nepo deppop wodniw oediv a
seirtnuoC woL eht fo noiL ehT
?sucigleB rM
sdnoces wef a retfA
,ylthgirb tuo doots dah yeht ,ecnO
,ytivitaerc fo tsrub siht yb detsuahxe ,neht ,depyt eh
”?snoitseuq ynA“
ytefas ro krow rof gnikool ereh emac ohw elpoep wen eht
.enam sih tuo koohs dna kcab daeh sih dessot oeL
,rae sih otni delworg ehs
,dloc nur kni sih edam llits yromem ehT
#  .seye deruoloc-tnemhcrap sih ni
snoil lanoitan fo ecneidua ehT
.dluoc esle enoyna erofeb ,deksa oeL ”?rats par a sa reerac feirb ym ot gnirrefer uoy erA“
sredrob eht taht deciton dah rehpargotrac citsitra emos ,ecnassianeR eht fo syad ylrae eht ni kcaB .llabddo
.derebmemer evila esle ydobon tsap a erahs dna tisiver dluoc eh woN
.ekoj yldduc ,yltrop A
.lausu sa nodnoL ni yhtliF
,woble thgir sih raen ,egèiL no ni demooz eh nehW
?ris…s’dlanoDcM ta tfel nrut dna teerts taht pu daeH .erehT“
”.sucigleB rM ,esaelp ,oruE neveS“
.essenoyL htiw ssem t’ndid uoY
,emit emas eht ta ,teY
erusaert fo serots sih ffo gnilles yb dednuf eh segakcap erac eht dna
enam a dah ehs yhw dna ,aciremA fo ssol eht ekil
,sredrob lanoitan dlo eht yb detatcid epahs sih
.ku.oc.reetyksuh ta
)tniop siht no raelc yleritne demees ydobon(
mih ssorca denael ssertiaw ehT
.tnemyolpmenU .msirorreT
;gnillevarnu saw dlrow elohw eht taht
”,slefawpoortS“ ”?sgniht ytiucsib lemarac esoht fo emos gnignirb uoy erA
.wap revlis a desiar sliaT-owT veL
.esrow raf erew sgniht erehw secalp morf ni gnidworc seegufeR
gnicnad thgil wen a
.denworf ehS .deksa eh
.enot deticxe ,lufreehc a dah rettahc rieht fo rrup wol ehT
.ecafpam ,uoy ees ot yppah syawla s’enoyrevE
,eeffoc sih deppis dna ssertiaw eht deknaht oeL
.netfo os yreve yrtsepat wen a pu gnuh uoy fi
”?tsol uoy era yhW“
,reetyksuH yb ”seirtnuoC woL eht fo noiL ehT“
,ro dna selug dna
tlef ohw eno ylno eht t’nsaw eh taht desilaer eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.wodniw eht desolc eH
”…re…rof daeh ot deen uoy ,ees s’teL“
.sretirw noitcif dna“ ,dias eh
.ffP“  .emit drah a reh evig derad ydobon taht hcus erew
.noitalosnoc roop a neeb dah reciffo RP eht gnitae neve dna
.delbmurc redrob a
”.su dna ,ytitnedi rieht esol ll’yeht diarfa er’ew dna ,seiteicos reggib
.ecnalg a mih deraps esle ydoboN
.oot stib dab ehT .wonk uoy ,muigleB fo yrotsih elohw eht yduts ot dah I .taht ton s’tI“
”?uoy erew ,muigleB ni nrob t’nerew…uoY“ .desuap neht