.srae nwo sih ot yrruls dednuos eciov siH
yhw s’tahT .noitpurroc fo ligis a si siht taht kniht
.diviv llits saw kcatta s’gniht-tac eht fo yromem eht tub
.mih no denrut ehs hcihw ,elims ecivres remotsuc tnenamrep a gnitrops dna
.nogard neesnu emos fo gnihtaerb eht ekil enigne denutrevo eht fo dnuos eht htiw gnitarbiv ,evac a saw tI
deb taht ni ereht tis lliw uoY
.htaenrednu yal taht arua eht fo remmilg tsetniaf eht tsuj ees dluoc eh thguoht osla eh tub
.rehto eht ot rac eht fo edis eno morf tfihs naht erom elttil did tnanever eht tub
,redrum laturb a evlos pleh ot
.llewriats eht otni deppils dna srotavele eht dna dworc eht detriks drawetS dna oehT
.ta gnitteg er’uoy tahw ees I tuB“ .derettum oehT
knip saw eniltuo reH
.revocsid ot ,uoy rof dna
deb eht fo ffo tpael evah dluow eH
.sgnul sih morf ria eht evird ot hguone drah tlebtaes eht otni demmals drawetS
,drawpu daeh sih denarc drawetS ,rood eht evoba eldnah eht gnihctulc llitS
lacisyhp a sah flesti hcihw ,esruc a yb detaerc tnanever fo dnik a si regnägredeiw A .tnanever a s’tahT
,taht gnitcepxe neeb t’ndah esuom ehT
,mih dlot oehT ”,og uoY“
.ecaf ruoy dehctarcs evah tsum gniht tahT“ .elims mirg a mih evag oehT dna
.ti ni neppah taht sgniht driew eht gnivlos ni sezilaiceps ohw enoemos sdeen ytic eht ekil smees tI“
gninrom txen eht ylrae tub
,swodniw detnit eht fo tuo ees dluoc oehT woh dnatsrednu t’ndluoc drawetS .tuo dellup
.meht dniheb gnituohs delffum dna hsarc a draeh drawetS
,sdrawtuo gniylf ,yawllah eht ni sniev eht ekil ,ygrene fo spihw fo segamiretfa yltsohg eht was eH
.yllaciteroeht ,seY“ .deredisnoc oehT
.secnamrofrep retteb ym fo enO
gniliec eht ni srellor morf gnignah sniatruc egieb yllanoitutitsni
daeh sti dna ti dna
.redluohs sih revo ecnalg a mih tohs oehT
rotinom retupmoc egral A
.dednetxe swalc ,woleb morf egreme dnah s’tnanever eht ees ot hguone gnol tsuj detatiseh drawetS
.evitceted ,ezilaer uoy naht elba erom flesruoy dnif lliw uoy kniht I ,tuB
.netfo yrev emoh ti ekam ton did esrun eht hguoht sa
.ecanem krad fo lluf eciov sih ,dias oehT
,gnikaeps saw eh sdrow eht raeh
tsehc eht otni sdnah sih teg ot deganam tub
,nezorf flesmih dnuof eh taht s’reed eht ekil hcum os dekool tI
.tnemtrapa s’reed eht ni nees dah eh ligis fo tros emas eht saw tI
.llaw eht ta evrac ot deunitnoc tub ,dnopser ot mih rof tiaw t’ndid ehS .deksa ehs
”?daeh ehT“ ”.tnenopmoc
”,elbatiusnu tsom eb dluow doolb yM“
.egalfuomac fo dnik a erew seigrene esohw
.erom yna enoyna rehtob t’now ehS“
,htob meht ta delims knim eht ”,yako ,lleW“
.deb latipsoh eht rof etomer eht mih dednah dna ytip koot oehT litnu
”?ereht ton s’eh fi dnA“
.ereh dnuora kcits ot nosaer on
,tneilc melborp a htiw sisirc a dah dah knuks eht
”,pu em kcab ot enoemos esu dluoc I“
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
,ti ees dluoc eh ,esolc sihT
.ssenkrad eht ni noisserpxe s’knuks eht tuo ekam t’ndluoc eh tub
.deid ydaerla sah ti naht erom yna ,eid t’now
.kcen sih leef ot nwod tlenk esuom eht dna ,oehT deppord tnanever ehT
,erom yna thgis s’drawetS morf taht gnidih on saw ereht
.esac ni tsuj ,tuo ti kcehc ot tsigolomlahthpo na ot larrefer a uoy teg ll’I tuB
.shguorob rehto eht fo eno rof tfel t’ndah yeht erus saw eh hguoht
,mih rof si degnahcnu siht morf kcab emoc sah eh rehtehW
.demaercs ylraen divaD dna nepo welf niatruc ehT .lanoisnemid owt
.yllacisyhpatem dna yllaretil htob ,doolb ni derots ygrene s’erehT
”.ecnis riahc siht ni gnittis neeb evah
.rekihhctih flowerew
.nellaf dah eh hcihw ni
”?drawetS .rM ,yadot gniod ew era woH“
,pu gnillew doolb eht tlef
,esnopser a rof gnitiaw tuohtiw ,dna gniteerg fo yaw yb dias oehT ”,evitceteD“
nwod ti etirw ot togrof yeht eciwt dna
”thgiS ehT“   yojne esaelP
.mih ta decnalg oehT
ot detnaw yllaer t’ndah I ,gninrom siht retfa dnA“
.demaercs esuom eht ”!oN“
”.won mih evael ylbissop t’ndluoc I ,on ,oN“
”,evitceted ym em teg oG
epacse ot tpmetta nwo s’drawetS ro
.noitanicullah fo dnik emos ekil
”?tuo I saw gnol woH“
.daeh s’tac eht tuo llup dna
”.ti fo erus m’I ,gniod s’eh si ti revetahw ot yrassecen si
.deksa drawetS ”?uoy era tahW“
nwod etorw yeht sserdda ehT
,tuo emac dnuos on tub ,devom shtuom riehT
.dias drawetS ”,pleh nac I“
.gnisir cinap ,dias drawetS
hguohT .evitceted ,gnidnif peek uoy sesac egnarts dna driew eht no tnatlusnoc ruoy m’I“
.sretnilps otni ti gninrut ,flehskoob eht otni dehsarc hcihw ,ygrene eht rednu dekcud eh dna ,niaga tuo gnuws ehS
…eht dluoW“ ”.scificeps eht wonk t’nod I tub ,devlovni cigam lautir s’erehT“ .mih deirrow tI .noisserpxe s’knuks eht ekil t’ndid eh dnuof drawetS .dettifmocsid gnikool ,deggurhs oehT ”?edam yeht era woH“ ”.regnägredeiw latnedicca on era erehT
.ybbol eht ot yaw eht del dna leeh sih no denrut oehT
”,nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI“
morf edih t’nac uoY“
.sgnidnuorrus railimafnu ni pu ekow drawetS divaD  2 fo 2 traP
.seidob tsol rieht dna sdaeh eht neewteb noitcennoc eht rof gnileef
,arua sselroloc ylegnarts sih rof tpecxe
”.ydaerla semit eerht deirt s’tI
.ti dniheb rewop gnicanem eht dna
,llaw raf eht tsniaga deldduh erew
s’ti ekiL .flesti ni kcuts ,naem I ,oN“
.yawllah eht ni ,reh tsap tsuj deremmilg gnihtemoS
,stnapucco s’tnemtrapa ehT
.dil eht gninepo flesmih dnuof eh tub ,epacse dna wodniw eht tuo bmilc ot ,knurt eht hcuot ot ton mih dlot tcnitsni yrevE
.ylsuoibud ,dias oehT ”,sseug I“
fo oirt a fo mrof eht ni ,dniheb tfel dah swalc s’tac eht racs eht ees ,yaw a ni ,dluoc drawetS
”.detcepxe I ohw ton er’uoY“
”.gnihtemos ro krow ot kcab og ot dah uoy yas tsuj ll’I ,enif s’tI“
.ehcadaeh eht snialpxe tahT“
”.tuo si nus eht ’,ti teg‘
”.ti htiw tnasaelp gnihtyna rewop t’ndluoc uoY
”?uoy derih dah ohw nam eht thguoht uoY“
.gnilaeh ta doog ytterp si aenroc ehT“
,ni dehcaer ,noitadipert htiw ,dna etarc eht fo tnorf ni tlenk eH
,regnägredeiw a yllacinhceT“ ”?tnanever a s’tahW“
”?evitceted ,taoc wen A“
.tekcub a saw edis reh tA
tneiciffus eb dluohs taht
.dluoc eh sa gnidliub tnemtrapa neesnu eht dna
.esle enoyna ni cinap dellac evah dluow drawetS tahw ot esolc eciov sih ,dias oehT ”!oN“
.mih hctef ot emac esrun eht litnu dengier ,tsal ta ,ecnelis dna
.deddon knuks ehT ”?oehT“
,tnemom a rof ffo deliart eH ”…I“ .mih dlot oehT
.sdaeh fo elip a saw knurt eht edisnI ”.divaD
llaw tnemtrapa eht hguorht naelc enog dah rac ehT
.rehtie ,ees dluoc drawetS sa raf sa tsael ta ,won ereht ton saw ehS
.tuo kcalb ot hguone drah daeh ruoy demmals uoy
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitseuq eht derongi eH
yaw eht yb ,esineD si eman reh—esrun eht ti ot ees ll’I
.aenroc ruoy ot egamad emos saw ereht tub
.sdaorssorc eht ta lived eht htiw tcap ehT .eripmav a fo etib ehT .meht
,oehT sdrawot denrut eH
”,revo lluP“ ”.tihS“
”.gnihtyreve nialpxe lliw dnabsuh ruoy erus m’I“
”?yako ,hguoht dekcehc ti teg uoy litnu taht ekil gnihtyna ro evird t’ndluohs ylbaborp uoY
.drawrof flesti dellup erutaerc eht sa etercnoc eht fo spirts tuo deguog yehT
.eerf hctal tlebtaes eht dehcnerw dna revo dehcaer oehT
.ees ot tsaf oot tsomla ,teef sih ot tohs oehT dna
,t’nsi cigaM“ .dias oehT
,rac eht ot desserp erew sregnif stI
,lausunU“ ”.won sgniht ees
,erusaelp taerg htiw os did eH
”?taht ekil doolb sdeen ohW .gnihtyreve morf“
.riahcleehw a mih thguorb seilredro eht fo eno sa noos sa tuo kcehc dluoc eh mih gnillet erofeb redluohs eht no mih dettap ehs dna
”?foor eht nO“ ”?kcuts s’ti ekil
.ylidaets drawetS gnihctaw
.derevihs eh dna nibac eht fo gniliec eht dehcuot wap siH
dna ti rof nur a ekam ll’I“ .dias drawetS
”.fo draehnu ton tub
drawetS .nirg suourgnocni ,ediw taht gnimaeb llits ,dias knim eht ”,won ,woN“
,gnikrow htuom s’oehT ees dluoc drawetS
,emit driht eht dna
,rab nori na hguorht hsup ot gniyrt ekil saw tI
.llaw etisoppo eht tih ot ecaps hguorht welf eh dna kcab sih otni demmals toh dna yvaeh gnihtemoS
.em tsurt ,yenoh ,regnad ni si eno devol a nehw si ti woh wonk I !esruoc fo ,hO“
,daeh sih raen pu tes saw
.gniht gnivil a naht rehtar gnitniap a ekil ,divaD ot talf dekool eH
.hcraeser emos od ot evah ll’I“ .deggurhs oehT
.retal taht rof emiT“
”.tnanever eht esaeler ot
.dnuora gninrut tuohtiw ,dias esuom eht ”,drawetS .rM“
.sebut dna seriw egnarts fo yteirav a ot dehcatta
,elpoep noillim thgie s’erehT“ .deksa drawetS
”,noissucnoc a evah uoY“
.sniatruc eht htiw dessuf ehs sa
.sfhf ta elbaliava
.deredduhs esuom eht
.ytpme saw deb ehT
,dehsinav eniltuo eht taht dnuof dna
.riahcleehw eht fo tuo gnibmilc ,deil eh
,eb dluoc yeht ytic eht ni erehw aedi on dah drawetS taht semit ynam os denrut dah yehT .srednatsyb gnisruc erom fo surohc a ot tfel a dekooh eH
,taht ot rewsna na evah t’ndid drawetS
.latipsoh eht fo tuo mih gnileehw saw knim eht
,taorht sih deraelc drawetS ”…tahW“
,knurt euqitna ,egral a saw ti ot txen dnA
.sregnif reh no doolb fo gnitaoc kciht eht rof tpecxe
.kcen sih fo ffurcs eht yb oehT gniggard ,tnanever eht saw reh ot txeN
.noitnetni fo tca na sekat ti esuaceb
.kcab reh ta thgilhsalf laet a gninihs saw enoemos ekil
,nwod dekool yeht ,eno sA
”.daeh ruoy koot I ecno mih llik uoy evah ot gniog saw I ,ytip A
.tuo detniop oehT
,eniltuo eulb tniaf a ni dednuorrus saw ehS
”.tnemtrapa taht fo tuo uoy gnitteg eltneg oot t’nsaw I .diarfa m’I ,tluaf ym saw taht fo emoS .doolb
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sroolf driht dna dnoces eht neewteb gnidnal eht ot nwod gniklaw
.elop VI na morf gnuh gab enilas A
,mih ta deknilb drawetS
.gninworf ,reh dlot eh ”,yakO“
.boj siht rof derih eb d’I taht kniht nac I nosaer ylno eht s’tI
.evoba roolf eht no gnorw saw gnihtemos esnes dluoc drawetS ,roolf dnoces eht yB
.nwod uoy pleh ot elba saw I neht dna
.revoc rof evod eh dna
.slativ s’drawetS koot ehs sa oehT htiw klatllams sseldnim otni despal neht
.emit gnol a rof eeffoc sih otni derats dna
sgniht ydlrowrehto
,ereht ton s’ti fi dna tnemtrapa eht ni rof gnikool er’uoy tahw dniF
”.melborp on ,pan kciuq a retfa kcab emoc dluoc uoY
,pu tis ot delggurts eh sa denaorg drawetS
.lian eht htiw ekil ,hcuot yb daerps nac ,dab ro doog rof ,cigaM
,s’reed eht ot ylralimis yrev tuo dial saw tnemtrapa s’knim ehT
.moor latipsoh a fo gnitniap a ta gnikool saw eh hguoht sa tlef drawetS
.noitisopmoced fo llems eht htiw kciht saw moor eht dna
”.uoy gnivael ton m’I“
.gnorw ti tog yeht
.yawrood eht morf delrans esuom eht
.ria eht ni pu esuom gnilggurts eht gnidloh llits
”?uoy eb ot sah ti dnA“ ”.sesnefed eht
,sesuac tnanever a yb dekcatta gnieb egamad lautirips dna lacisyhp eht morf edisa yllatoT“
.yddaC eht fo roiretni krad eht otni deppils neht dna
,nommoc ylralucitrap era lareneg ni stnanever taht ton ,erar er’yehT“ .deddon oehT
,elims fo dnik gnirepmis ,daorb a saw tI
,enrohtwaH .S.J yb
”,reh fo erac ekat lliw I“
.knuks eht dlot eh
,eye derujni sih desolc eh ,yllatnemirepxE
.reh retfa mitciv rehtona detnaw pu siht tes reveohW
.tnemtrapa eht fo tuo deklaw
.noitnetta on meht diap drawetS
,seitilamronba on delaever nacs TC ehT
ylgninoitseuq oehT ta revo dekool eH ”?…yM“
.arua nwo s’oehT fo roloc-non eht htiw dellif taht
”?syadhtrib tuoba tahW“
reddal eht ot teg ot retspmud a no pu debmilc I .epacse
renroc eht morf pu flesmih dekcip ylsuoituac eh sa drawetS dewollof seye sih tub
.elpoep ta dekool eh nehw tcepxe ot emoc dah eh olah eht fo ecnesba eht ,diov a saw sreH
”.taht ekil sesac ekat ot gniyrt trats thgim I kniht I
.mih dedivorp dah oehT noops revlis eht htiw eeffoc eht derrits drawetS
daeh dna regnägredeiw eht gnitcennoc dna gnidnuorrus thgil eht
,esac ni tsuj ,sesrun eht fo tsom dna rotcod ruoy sa llew sa
.esiwrehto uoy llik
,mih dnuora thgil egalfuomac eht ees dluoc flow ehT
”,nwod wols ,oehT ?oehT“
.mih ecaf ot denrut dna
.gnirewsna fo daetsni nwod kcab tas eh sa tius sih tuo dehtooms oehT
semit eerht sserdda eht evag I
,noisiv sih no erusserp a ekil saw tI
.sehctulc sti epacse ot deirt eh sa
.mra na htiw eye sih dleihs ot dah oehT taht tniop eht ot desaercni erusserp fo gnileef eht elihw
.noitatipaced yb dellik si tnanever a yllanoitidarT
.eye tfel sih detset dna thgil nep a tuo dellup ehs ,rewsna na rof gnitiaw tuohtiW
,evitceted ,uoy ssim dluow I“ .deggurhs oehT
”?naem uoy od tahW“
,siht did reveohw
.oot ,deneppah yllautca tahw ot sa sseleulc era ecilop ehT
.sarua rieht no dah sdrow sih tceffe eht ees dluoc drawetS dna ,meht dlot oehT
,yadhtrib s’esrun ruoy s’tahT“ ”?yhw ,haeY“
.eslup on s’erehT“
,dluoc eh sa ylluftcepser dna yltnerever sa ,ylregniG
”,emit revo retteb teg ll’tI“
,tekcub eht otni pord lian eht gnittel ,doots esuom ehT
,gniht yldlrowrehto
.htap rieht gnikram stsirotom suoiruf dna sessim raen fo ekaw a ,emit drocer ni ediS tsaE reppU eht ni gnidliub tnemtrapa s’knim eht dehcaer yehT
.dneirf knuks ruoy gnillik yltnerruc si taht loot eht ekil ,loot A“
,ligis A“ ”?lobmys cigam a ekiL
htiw tcatnoc evah ohw esoht egnahc nac
.lian dlo na htiw llaw eht otni gnihtemos devrac ehs sa drawetS ot kcab reh htiw gnileenk saw ,snaej eulb
,ereh ti dloh ylno nac I“ .mih dlot knuks eht
neeb ev’yehT“ .ti noitseuq ot ton dias sgnaf gnimaelg ,prahs ,gnol ehT
.mih ta doolb eht gnikcilf hguoht sa ,drawtuo sdnah reh gnulf ehS ”.em pots
”.eye eno tsuj htiw gnol os retfa gnitsujdaer tsuJ .haey ,hU“
.setunim otni hcterts ecnelis eht gnittel
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.evitceted ,em dnatsrednusim uoY“
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht fo rebmem duorp A
,evitceted ,talf gnikool sgniht sA
.deksa oehT ”?tnanever ehT“
.thgin erom eno drawetS gnipeek no detsisni rotcod eht tub
.ecamirg lufniap a deganam ylno dna ,kcab elims ot deirt eH
.drawetS ot elbisivni gnidliub a sdrawot gnitniop
.elihw a rof ylno dna
noitpurroc dna ecanem eht gnikatsim on saw ereht ,tnemtrapa s’reed eht ekilnU
,detnit yllagelli swodniw sti
.snroh gniknoh dna stuohs delffum emac rac eht edistuo dna ,tlahpsa eht tsniaga delaeuqs serit ehT
”.elssah laminim htiw tnemtrapa reh ecalper ot elba si—
.siht yojne ot gniog m’I“
”,yltnatropmi tsom dnA
”.ti dehcuot uoy nehw uoy ot daerps taht noigatnoc lacigam a
?tser sruoh wef a teg dna emoh teg ot tnaw t’ndluow uoy erus uoy era
,esuops lufitud ruoy ,I dna revo edir rac eht no ssensuoicsnoc tsol uoY
”.tuo dnif dluohs ew kniht I“
dnoces a tsuj rof
,llits tnew yltpurba neht ,rewsna ot detrats oehT
.dnuorg eht ffo reh detfil eh dna taorht s’esuom eht dnuora depparw dnah sih sa thgil der doolb fo olah a laever ot
dlo dna trihs-t dedaf a gniraew
.deddon drawetS .deksa oehT
knurt eht morf emac thgil erom on litnu
.wollip sih tsniaga kcab
,ti fo tsrow eht morf uoy detcetorp
,ssenkrad eht ni ,tnemezama sih oT
,elbat moor gninid etanro s’oehT ta tas drawetS
.bruc eht detnuom ylfeirb serit eht sa pmuht tfos a saw erehT .elcric-imes a ni gniddiks rac sih ,deeps ta nrut-U a dellup oehT ”.knim eht
.yrujni eht denimaxe rotcod eht elihw yltneitap tis ot detnesnoc neve eh niaga gnikrow seye htob evah ot desaelp os saw dna
”.citnamor sselepoh a syawla saw oehT“
.enecs eht fo tcepsa talf ylerrazib eht yb decnahne ylno saw gnileef laerrus tahT
.dnuos yb tnanever eht kcart ot gniyrt
.ti tpmetta ot htgnerts eht dekcal ydob sih dna
,gnitarg ti dnuof
.egalfuomac lautirips fo dnik emos ekil
era erus woH“ ”.roolf driht eht no si tnemtrapa reH“ .pu dekool neht ,deddon oehT ”.hguoht ,nekorb s’gnihtoN .retal truh nac I .kniht I ,desiurB“ ”?thgirla uoy erA
.eye sih ni gnihsalf tpek ehs thgil eht sa hcum sa
.rehto hcae ta neht
.ti tuoba deksa eh nehw
”.ainavlysnneP ni saw
.niaga nwod mih gninnip oehT dnuof dna deb fo tuo flesmih llup ot detrats eH
.niaga delims oehT
.derepsihw eh ”,ti ees nac I“
.esaeler t’nac ti erusserp rednu
”?ts1 yaM ?yaM yas uoy diD“
.noisiv s’divaD fo edistuo gnihtemos ta erats ot pu gnippans daeh
flesmih neewteb ecnatsid hcum sa tup ot troffe elituf a ni roolf eht tsniaga teef sih gnilbbarcs ,eldnah barg eht ta dewalc eH
.nelots dah ehs gniht rehtonA .dezilaer eh ,hteet s’esle enoemoS
.wolley letsap fo skaerts htiw tohs
.deganam drawetS ”?deneppah tahW“
tsap ti sekam ti esac ni ereh eb ot sdeen enoemos tub
ot deneppah gnihtemoS
dluoc I tnedifnoc erew I fi nevE“ .detrons oehT
.emit ym rof uoy gnigrahc trats dluohs I leef I
.htaed naht esrow etaf a ot mih gard ot detiaw serutaerc sseldaeh on dna
”?gnihtemos rewop ot ebyam tub ,doolb gnimusnoc ton oS“
”.uoy ot neppah elbakaepsnu gnihtemos dluohs
.tekcaj yffup eht fo seveels eht ta gniggut ,oehT dlot eh
pu denepo ti ,em dehsals
.llew krow syawla t’nseod gnidrocer cinortcele dna
,solah eugav eht ni mrof ot nugeb dah skcarc elttiL
.etteuohlis s’erutaerc eht fo hcteks elap a ekil erom tub
.thguof regnägredeiw eht dna oehT sa tabmoc fo sdnuos eht dna hsarc a draeh eh ,mih dniheB
,rood tnorf eht tuo dehsur neht
.kcab emac ti nehw nruter ot ylno
,evarg eht sa llits saw knuks ehT
.gnorw elttil a tsuj ton dnA
.dael a evah ll’ew ebyam nehT“
nwod noops eht tes drawetS
,kcab sih ta hsals swalc sti tlef eH
.foor s’rac eht no duht tfos eht dessim evah dluow eh ,drah os gninetsil neeb ton eh daH
,foor eht ta pu detniop eh
,yltneuqerf sdnah sih hsaw ot mih gnisivda revasneercs sti
:ecneirepxe na dah dna
”.edir a hctih ot dediced sah dneirf ruo kniht I .ti draeh I“
,seye sih ni wolg eht gnikatsim on saw erehT
,sgnaf s’krahs fo lluf htuom a gnilaever ,mih ta dennirg ehs
.niaga kcatta ot gniraperp ,pu derauqs ehs sa yliraw reh deye eH
”.thgirla eb ll’eh erus m’I litnu ton tsael tA“
.mih ta nwod gnilims knuks eht dnuof dna
.llet dluoc eh ,mih gnikcom saw ehS ”’.tneilc‘
”,edir ruoy si siht kniht I“
”,taht morf yawa yatS“
”.hctap eye na gniraew er’uoy
.goD fo ecioV ehT no
”?yaM ni nrob uoy ereW“
.roiretni s’rac eht rof mret a dlim oot saw kraD
.thgilyad thgirb eht otni degreme yeht sa mih dlot esrun eht
dekcilc rood eht sa noos sA
.dednamed drawetS
…ekil s’tI .wonk t’nod I“
”,etad tsrif ruo ekil tsuJ“
.ecaf s’drawetS no noisufnoc eht gnihctac ,denialpxe eh
.doolb dlo fo hcnets suoixon eht llems dluoc eh dna
.hgual a decrof drawetS
.esrun eht sdrawot denrut knuks ehT
,deb a no gniyl saw eH
.latem eht otni gniggid erew swalc sti denigami drawetS dna
.delworg drawetS ”,enif leef I“
mih derussa rotcod eht
ruoy was uoy ekil eno taht was reed ehT
”?esuom eht ot deneppah
.ylthgil mih ekop ot revo dehcaer drawetS litnu
.nepo ydaerla rood regnessap eht ,bruc eht ta dekrap saw
?thgir ,tnemtrapa eht fo edistuo ro edisni
”.noitcelloc ym rof luos rehtona teg em pleh ot
.tnemom taht ta sraet wef a dehs evah yam I“
,detah syawla dah drawetS
”.sruoh tsap mih htiw yats em gnittel rof niaga uoy knahT“
.txen semoc revetahw ot no ssap tonnac ti ,htaed retfa neve ,taht os hself nwo sti ot dnuob emoceb nac ti ,ecitsujni evarg a tlaed si luos a nehW“ .dehgis oehT
,mahguorB 9891 egatniv A
.ezeeuqs a ti evag dna s’drawetS otni wap sih deppils oehT
lluks kciht ruoy yltnerappa ,dab oot ton s’ti syas rotcod ehT
,tac eht fo sniamer lateleks eht ta
.noisiv ym detceffa s’ti kniht I dnA
”?reh s’ti taht uoy
.dewollof drawetS ,ria rof gnipsag llitS
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
suoicsnocnu drawetS dekconk ohw retsnom sseldaeh a
”,etunim a eb ot gniog ylno erew uoy dias uoY .etad a dah ew esuaceb uoy htiw emoc dah I tub
serutcarf enilriah tsellams eht
deppord arua sih fo roloc-non egalfuomac ehT
.emoh teg ot mih rof stnemegnarra edam ydaerla dah tub
.drawetS rof gnitiaw tuohtiw nepo rood sih gnivohs ,dias eh ”,no emoC“
.rood roolf driht eht rof nar dna denrut eH
.elttil a depleh tI
,drawetS ot tsol saw tuoba klat ot detnaw oehT revetahW
esopmoced ot nageb
.gninthgil rolocinhcet htiw dehsalf arua esohw ro ,blubthgil erab a ta gnikool ekil saw ti esnetni os thgil fo submin a yb dednuorrus enoemos dessap eh neht dna won yreve tub ,wolg eugav a dah elpoep tsoM
.em sa yadhtrib emas eht dah reed ehT“
,reh tuoba egnarts gnihtyna saw ereht nwonk evah t’ndluow eh ,teerts eht no reh dessap dah eh fI
,ti leper ot deganam dna
.redluohs s’flow eht no dnah sih dah llits ton dah oehT fi
,deb latipsoh a ni pu dnuow eh woh fo tnuocca lanoitcif eht debircsed oehT sa ,dna derit ylbatnuoccanu leef ot gnitrats saw drawetS
,dezilaer eh ,tcaf nI
.ot detnaw I esuaceB .htgnerts dna rewop em evag ti esuaceB .dluoc I esuaceB“
.eye sih desolc eH
.esolc dna nepo rood ybbol eht draeh yeht ,roolf driht eht ot debmilc dah yeht erofeB
,delims oehT ”?uoy era tahW“
retnab kciuq dna rennam ysae s’knuks eht
.saw eh erehw dezilaer eh nehw s’tahT
.regna fo lwoh reh yb egduj ot
,elims a reh dereffo eH
.kool ot eye sih denepo dna dehgis drawetS
”.oot ,erofeb mitciv a saw ereht ylbaborP
.kcen reh ot dehcatta ylmrif
.eciov talf esiwrehto s’knuks eht ni noitasucca fo tnih a saw erehT
.pu werht ylraen dna ,moor latipsoh eht enimaxe ot daeh sih denrut eH
”?gnippohs tnew uoy oS“ ”.enola eb
.foor eht ot gnignilc tac sseldaeh eht fo eniltuo tniaf a ees dluoc eh
”,cigam fo dnik A .kniht I ,ruomalg a s’erehT .yrroS“
.seninac gnol sih ffo gniwohs
.erew sessim rieht fo emos raen woh wonk ot detnaw eh kniht t’ndid eh—
.niaga ksa ot deirt neht
.riats eulb yci sih htiw ecalp ni mih ezorf oehT erofeb nwod pets eno koot eH
”.yad rehtona rof tfel retteb
.mih ta daeh reh dekcoc ehS
deworrob I“ ,dedda eh ,kool suoludercni s’drawetS ot esnopser nI
,thguorb dah oehT taht snaej dna trihs wen dnarb a revo tekcaj dedderhs sih gniraew ,retal setunim ytnewT
”,detcennoc era sgniht eseht taht tbuod oN“
swodniw detnit eht fo tuo ees t’ndluoc eh dalg leef ot nageb drawetS
,oehT ta sreggad derats drawetS
,boj a no erew uoy meht dlot I“
,niaga ecno thgin eht yats mih gnittel otni ffats eht klat ot deganam oehT
.ta kool ot lufniap
,dias eh hcihw ni riahc llat eht ni kcab denael oehT
,eb ll’uoy ekil noos dnA“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ti egdolsid ot gniyrt ,snrut neddus erom lareves edam oehT
,yleugav deddon elpuoc ehT
.erus eb ot hcraeser emos od ot evah d’I hguoht ,elbissop stI ?naem uoy
?ti etavitca ot llaw eht no gnihtemos ward ot deen yeht dluow
.dlrowrednu eht otni yenruoj ehT
.detraped esrun eht yllautnevE
.ehca ot sdnuow ynam sih denigami eh
nossirf yrotaderp s’oehT rehtie deciton evah ot mees t’ndid esrun ehT
”.nacs TC a tnaw ot gniog si rotcod eht ,tuoba dna pu er’uoy taht woN“
.nibac eht dnoyeb thgis fo kcal sih rof pu ekam ot daetsni gniniarts srae sih
”,sgniht wef a fo kniht nac I“
,rotaderp a saw oehT
,gnihtyreve revo dialrevo senil rulb tniaf
”?neht ,txen s’ehs kniht uoY“
erif eht fo sthgilf wef a nwod llef dna wodniw eht hguorht dehsarc uoy nehw edistuo uoy rof gnitiaw saw I meht dlot I ,yawynA
”?won od uoy lliw tahW
,lleW“ .dehgis drawetS
.emoh rieht otni dehsarc ohw enilef eht tuoba gnilley
.sroloc fo noitanibmoc ro roloc tcnitsid a eno hcae ,arua na dah dessap eh enoyrevE
retcarahc nootrac a fo nrettap gnitaeper eht ni derevoc sburcs ni desserd
”.doolB“ ”.nalp a deen eW .regnol hcum pu siht peek t’nac eW“
,mih ta gnirats oehT thguac eh ,eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuO
”,ybab ,em ot doog os
,elpuoc dega elddim a
nepo syawla rood ym dnif lliw uoy dnA
,llew sa ,ria desusid yleugav a
.knurt eht revo gnippirt ylraen ,kcab pets a koot dna ylitsah ti deppord drawetS .yldipar
.rood eht denepo eh sa noos sa
tahW“ .deddon drawetS
”,deniur saw eno dlo ehT“
,derevihs drawetS
.drawrof desserp drawetS ,tnemgduj retteb sih tsniagA
tol gnikrap eht ni ti thguac I ,emit tsrif ehT“ ”?tahW“
.hsart eht dniheb ,llaw nehctik eht no devrac gnihtemos saw erehT“ ”?yhW
.eciov decitcarp ,reppihc a ni deksa ehs
,enrohtwaH .S.J yb ”thgiS ehT“
.dellac esuom eht
.gnitsixe fo esnes on
.weiv morf moor eht fo tsom gnikcolb
,oehT dneirf sih fo pleh eht thguos ,eye etavirp ,drawetS divaD ,emit tsaL   .degnahcnu secneirepxe eseht morf kcab emoc ton od eW .ssyba eht otni kool gnol ehT
dah tI .shpargotohp fo daetsni sevlehskoob dna sgnitniap tcartsba htiw hguoht
.sriats fo sthgilf lareves hguorht neve elbisiv ,arua egnarts eht gnikatsim on saw erehT
,ti denommus ohw rerecros eht taefed uoy fI .ffo ti dloh ll’I“
,ti morf tuo detaidar taht rewop fo arua eht ees dluoc eh tub ,ti otni ees t’ndluoc drawetS
,rac eht fo tuo tog tac egral A“
dnuorg eht ot despalloc tnanever ehT .tuo dekniw
.mih tih ehs fi neppah dluow tahw wonk ot tnaw t’ndid eH
daeh reh sah llits yletinifed tsomla ohw
”?gnihtyna htiw od ot evah taht seod tahW“
”.yaM ni nrob erew su fo eerht eht naht erom ylerus
,tpircsednon ylriaf ,esuom A
.eye na desiar oehT
t’nac uoy esuaceb“
dedne ti erehw ot gab eht morf enil eht dewollof eH
.erom yna ereht yllatot t’nsaw ehs ekil saw tI
.ycnegreme krow lacihtym emos tuoba enohp eht revo tnemugra duol a dekaf
.esuap a saw erehT .ylyrd dias oehT
,knim redlo na saw ehS
”?erac uoy od yhW“
.cinap dna regna fo xim a snoisserpxe rieht
,rulb rosnec a fo tcejbus eht hguoht sa ,sucof fo tuo ylegnarts saw ligis ehT .nekat dah drawetS serutcip eht pu dellup yeht rehtegot dna ,stceffe lanosrep sih fo elip llams eht morf enohp s’drawetS dehctef oehT ”.erutcip a koot I
,ekirts eht rednu evod neht ,kcatta txen reh rof detiaw eH
.hsarc citpylacopa na yb dewollof
”?thgirla gnihtyrevE“
.oehT dlot eH .tnemom a ni meht nopu eb dluow dna sriats eht pu sruof lla no gnilwarc saw erutaerc ehT
.ti sdrawot tuo gnihcaer ,dias drawetS
nac I .em ni gnihtemos
.wodniw a no skaerts niar ekil
.moordeb s’knim eht ni pu gnidniw dna llah eht nwod gnihsur
”.esuoh reh draug dneirf a evah ot esnecil s’revird reh
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.drawetS ta pu decnalg eh
.mih dekcatta tsrif dah tnanever eht erofeb tnemom eht ot kcab detropsnart neeb dah eh taht ,tnemom a rof ,niatrec
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
”?ffo ti llup ot yrt ,rood eht nepo I dluohS“
,ecneserp on dah ehS
,knurt eht ta decnalg drawetS
ti ro niap leef ot mees t’nseod ti tub
.dnah sih fo kcab eht ni
htiw tcatnoc dah uoy evah elpoep ynam woh tuB“
.tnanever eht yb dellik eb ot ereht erew uoy erus ekam ot erac koot tnaercsim eht dnA“
.erofeb elzzum s’knuks eht no nees reven dah eh noisserpxe na
”?yadhtrib ruoy erahs ohw
”,divaD ,em morf edih t’nac uoY“
.tfel eht ot drah leehw eht deknay knuks eht ,yltpurbA ”.no gnaH“
,emit gnol a rof taht detsegid drawetS
,luof os saw hsart eht
,bruc eht revo tnew yddaC eht sa etercnoc tsniaga latem fo laeuqs elbirret a saw erehT
.ti htaenrednu dekcud ohw ,drawetS sdrawot flesti dehcnual regnägredeiw ehT .gniht-tac eht dlot ehs
,ecived reggirt fo tros emos saw lian ehT
”?ereht llits ti sI“
.etar decnavda ylhgih a ta yaced ot ti gnisuac saw siht
taht drawetS dlot esrun knim eht dna ,taht retfa yltrohs dehsinav eH
”,ecilop eht ot tnemetats a evag I“
.evom ot ton mih gnillet ,redluohs sih no dnah dloc-eci eno ,tnatsni na ni edisdeb sih ta saw oehT
”?ti pots ew od woH“
,doolb dellems su fo rehtieN“ ”?em esucxE“
”.reisae sgniht ekam thgim taht ,daeh eht dah ew fI
”.em egrahcsid yeht nehw llac a uoy evig ll’I dna hcraeser eht no detrats teg uoy t’nod yhW
”.thginot uoy dnif ll’I .nur
.deneppah dah tahw rehtegot eceip ot deirt yeht sa rehto hcae revo gnituohs tser eht
.ti yned ot dehsiw flow eht sa hcum sa neve
”,divaD ,ti llik t’nac I“
.tlebtaes eht otni demmals dah ti erehw tsehc sih gnihctulc saw eH
ni yltnecer tsom saw krow s’.S.J
.gnilooc yldipar ,mih fo tnorf ni retsaoc elttil taen a no eeffoc fo puc a
”.syad wef a rof hctap eht raew ot evah ll’uoY
.edisni tif ot nosrep a rof hguone gib
,yltpurba ,dna dnuow gnikcus taerg a ekil dnuos a saw erehT .dellup dna
,dias oehT ”,si ti erehT“
.doow eht hguorht kcis dna elap enohs thgil yltsohg A
lliw tnanever eht esuaceb evael t’nac I
.gnilaeuqs serit ,denrut oehT
.eciov sih ni draeh reve dah drawetS naht htmraw erom htiw ,dias oehT
”?dootsrednu taht si ,evael ot uoy sraelc rotcod a litnu
.rotarelecca eht deroolf oehT ,gnirewsna fo daetsnI .deksa drawetS
”?no gnah ,naem uoy od tahW“ ”.no gnaH“
,niap lautca gnileef morf mih detneverp taht VI sih ni rellikniap ytud yvaeh emos saw ereht detcepsus eH
.moor gnivil detadtuo ylthgils a fo sniur eht ni won tas dna
,laer yleritne ,gnikaeps yllacigolotno
.reh gniciton dnoyeb saw drawetS tub ,egar ni demaercs esuom ehT
,enrohtwaH S.J yb ”thgiS ehT“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT      ”.uoy rof
.nacs TAC eht tnaw yeht yhw ylbaborp s’taht dna ,yllautca ,deirrow teg ot gnitrats erew yehT .diarfa m’I ,yad a etiuq toN“
fo tol a rehtar tsol uoy dnA“ .mih dlot oehT
taht deveileb netfo si tI  .kni.sfhf
I tub ,ytniatrec htiw llet ot drah s’tI
,sdnah doog ni si yllaer eH
tahwemos dekool gnihtyreve
”.regnol hcum ereh yats t’nac ew ,yaw rehtie tuB
.foor eht ot wol dna nwod dereknuh ,edistuo eht ot toof a dils gniht-tac ehT
eybdoog esrun eht dib eH
,mih ta tuo ekirts ot sdnah reh desiar ehS
”.kcab eht tuo nar dna ,knurd
.ti redisnoc lliw I“
,nees dah eh srehto eht ekil ton ,arua na t’nsaw tI
”.klawedis deweps egabrag a ffo ti kcus ot ylekil t’nera doolb no deef taht sgnihT
”.em esahc ot nwod spmuj ti nehw ti teg nac uoy
,eerf meht dellup eh ,eno yb enO
.llah eht fo dne eht ta rood nepo na morf gnitaname erew erusserp dna ygrene htoB
.hsart eht ni dnuof dah drawetS taht lian eht saw sa
.tnemtrapa eht gniduorhS“
.ciffart elbisivni eht fo tuo dna ni gnivaew elihw noitasrevnoc a dloh ot gnitpmetta knuks eht yb detrofmoc eh saw ron
”,su ees t’ndid uoY“
spahrep era niaga klaw ohw esoht neewteb snoitcnitsid enif eht hguoht
.deb eht otni kcab dexaler eh litnu yllooc ezag sih tem knuks eht tub
”.hpargotohp a ekil ,talf s’gnihtyrevE
.dnatsrednu t’ndid drawetS esion a edam oehT ”.esaeler
,won latipsoh eht dnuora noitcetorp artxe emos s’ereht dna srovaf wef a ni dellac I
noitcennoc taht rof dehcaer eh
,drow a tuohtiw ,dna
”.ti tuoba driew gnihtemos s’erehT“
elbisivni saw oehT tub ,taes s’revird eht ta detniuqs drawetS
.ffo hctap eye eht ekat dluoc eh mih dlot rotcod eht ,egrahcsid erofeb yltrohS
.niarb sih hcaer ot gninaem eht rof tnemom a mih koot ti tub
.niaga drawetS ees ot deveiler saw eh dias elims ehT
.tuoba erom wonk ot dedaerd dna detnaw ylsuoenatlumis eh gniht eht ot kcab mih thguorb dnim gninnips sih yllautnevE
.tnanever eht dna daeh eht neewteb noitcennoc egnarts eht
,yaw dab a ni si knuks ruoY .su
,oehT ta ylknalb gnirats flesmih dnuof drawetS
,oehT ro ,dekcolb tlef arua esohw ,tnanever eht ekil t’nsaw tI .arua on dah ehS
.ti ot txen reed eht dna ,elip eht fo pot no ,ereht s’tac eht was eH
.daor eht ot kcab noitnetta sih werd knoh a litnu drawetS ta erats ot denrut oehT
tac eht nehw deneppah revetahw ,kniht I“
.mih ta derats seye gnidaelp rieht dna
.deggurhs ehS .deksa eh ”?yhW“
,roolf dna sllaw eht gnola deslup ygrene fo sniev neerg kcihT
,edam ton fi ,naelc llits saw deb eht tuB
,secivres ycnegreme ot gnikaeps dna senohp no lareves ,rood tnorf eht raen derehtag elpoep fo puorg egral a saw erehT
.ssenisub lla niaga ecno gnimoceb ,tca dnabsuh detoved sih deppord oehT ,desolc
”.gnineve siht emoh ym ta uoy teem ll’I neht dnA“
”,em evoba thgir s’tI“
.niaga hteet krahs esoht gnilaever ,mih ta dennirg ehS
,detsuahxe ,despalloc eh ,msaps elbeef a retfA
”,gniht eht morf ,mitciv eht morf ,doolb eht lla
esruc eht no gnissap mitciv hcaE