!etaborper elbaresim uoy ,ereh gnieb em htiw gnorw gnihton s'ereht esuaceb em fo uoy eruc t'nac eH"
"?aedi doog a s'taht"
"!hcruhc cisotsoirepA eht fo sdnim lacigoloeht tsomerof eht fo eno ot pu dnats ot
,dab llems neve t'ndid srehto eht gnoma
,enildoolb rieht ot tcennoc uoy
"?tahw si ohW" "?ti si ohW"
egaruoc ro rogir lautcelletni eht evah dluow
",doog yna mih did ti taht toN" "'!tniaS laretiL a'
,hcuoc eht revo gnitaolf ,detaolg dahalaG
,erac t'ndid niawaG tub ,knird eht neeb evah tsum ,neerg tsomla
,niawaG drawot denael dna
,sepop ecnassianer gib tsal eht fo eno fo truoc
.mih dniheb gnidnats dnuohflow a fo noitcelfer eht ees dluoc eh
,elohssa na s'ohw dneirf a tog ev'uoy fI"
"!nekops eb nis ton teL"
,eip noino dna eseehc emos
!tnaived gnillappa uoy" ,dahalaG demaercs
".esaelp ,senildoolb .hU .uoy toN
.yrtogib s'dahalaG .tS ot pu dnats yllaer nac
strats tsuj dna mih tcepxe t'nod I nehw dnoces eht thgir sraeppA
.hsiler tnerappa htiw ti denwod
.tsermra eht tsniaga kcab yal kalitreB ".kO"
.dahalaG detnemmoc
.yllufthguoht ,nihc sih dehctarcs kalitreB ".huH" .kced
.lla ta gnihton dias d'eh fi sa evitceffe sa neeb dah
,nortaP ruoy htiw etacinummoc uoy woh s'dnob tahT"
.tcejbo ot mees t'ndid kalitreB tub ,luftneser gninrut eciov sih tlef
".did uoy nehw deneppah tahw was I tub"
?taht wonk kalitreB t'ndid ,yaw gnol a emoc d'eh taht noitanalpxe s'niawaG
sih no yrteop dna seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,esicrexe rof pu gniwohs t'nerew ,slaem rof pu gniwohs t'nerew uoy dias ,em dellac ycreP
.draug-ffo em hctac nac eh llit tiaw ot sekil eh tub"
,sdnob erom ekam uoy ,stirips erom teem uoY
"?uoy ekil t'nseod tsuj eH"
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
drah yletarepsed
.dnuohflow a s'eH"
,os gniod saw eh erawanu ,detcidartnoc kalitreB
"-tub ,ssalc ym fo daeha ,nortap a htiw tcatnoc edam ev'I dna slacitcarp ym dehsinif I"
mih revo dehsarc gnimaercs ylhtraenu fo ehcnalava na erofeb tsehc erab s'regdaB eht no sdnah sih ecalp ot tuo dehcaer dah eh taht dna
".hcum taht wonk I ,haeY"
seno eht fo eno ,onnud I
,wonk yeht sa raf sA
,eert samtsirhc gnittor dna ecirouqil eb tsum tahw fo ffins latnemirepxe na retfa ,dediced dah niawaG
",siht gniod ton er'uoY"
"?taht raeh uoy ...diD"
.nosrep retteb a eb ot yrt ot ecnahc a evresed t'nod I woh tuoba serutcel gnol-sruoh rO
,tey esoht tuoba hcum thguoht t'ndah I"
emit txen ni enuT
,gniklat trats dluow retpurretnI eht dnoces ynA .retpurretnI ehT
.tsugsid cidica ni desrup spil niht ,niawaG revo gnimool ,detuohs eh
.tcatnoc eye gnidloh ,kalitreB
".em ot uoy dnes annog saw eh diaS
.esoppus I ,tset ot elbisnes ylnO"
"?thgir ,dnob taht gninehtgnerts er'uoy ,eman a ti evig uoy nehW
.em ta gnimaercs ,moob ,tuo gnikam ro desserdnu er'ew sa nooS"
.ereht meht depmalc d'eh dezilaer dna ecaf sih ffo swap sih yrp yltneg enoemos tlef niawaG
,ecaf gnivorppasid
.suoigiler erocdrah erew
flesym ot siht gniod neeb ev'I"
,nem redlo rof gniht a dah hcum yrev niawaG dna ",erus uoy era ...I"
..." ".meht fo dir teg t'nac yeht drah os srotsecna rieht fo stirips eht lennahc nac"
"!?nam a ekil I YAS em tel neve t'now uoY"
.sretsiemregrub ro sekud ro sregawod htiw seicaripsnoc eht lla gnivah
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
.esnet sredluohs sih tlef niawaG
yrots s'yadot dna
,gnihcaet ssenisub on tog s'nam taht ,raews I
,sdraw ym od I woh ni yas a stnaw ycreP fI" .detrons kalitreB '.ssenihsalf' fo thguoht dah toleco eht tahw ,serutcel s'larGeD .forP fo emos fo gnikniht pleh t'ndluoc god ehT .denihw niawaG
niawaG ".serac eh fi wonk t'nod I"
.god eht rof ssalg rellams hcum a dna ssalg lluf a flesmih deruop dna lebal on htiw elttob a denepo dah regdab eht dna
eht otno gnilwarps tnew dna riahc oitap eht dednepu ,ecnalab tsol ,depmuj llits eh dna ti gnitcepxe neeb d'eH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT  .egar
,hU" .elbissop neeb evah dluohs naht reneerg erew seye siH
'yxes dnuos ti seod yhw' dna ,deksa niawaG "?naem uoy od tahW"
.mih ta deknilb kalitreB .niawaG detuohs
,ees dluoc niawaG ylno dnuohflow eht dereens
.daeh sih koohs niawaG
,demialced dahalaG .tS
"?uoy dluow ,si siht ohw wonk ot neppah t'ndluow uoY .ralucitrap ni
.gniees erew uoy sallef tnereffid eht htiw ffo sgniht ekorb uoy
zzuf keehc s'niawaG ekorts ot hguone esolc tog kalitreB ",wonk uoy ,ot
er'uoy ,tirips nortap ruoy teem uoy nehW"
?thgir ,dnob a gnihsilbatse
,floWcaM boR yb thgiN neerG ehT
.sdneirf on gnivah tnia rewsna eht
".nem htiW .xes ...evah I taht
.seye sih otni derats kalitreB
saw eh esilaer ot emit hguone dah niawaG ".enim yrt"
.gnitsugsid dna ,detrevrep m'I ekiL"
.drawretfa kced kcab eht no klat dna
.tpurretni ot gnihtemos mih evig s'tel neht ,lleW" ".gnihtemos
",tfarchctiw nehtaeh etareneged ruoy ylppa ot emuserp ton oD"
,no derekcilf yehT
.mih ot klat t'ndid nortap sih yhw aedi tneced a dah eh noitnem t'ndid niawaG ".em ta kool
.egelloc ta elbuort gnivah er'uoy
"?won knird taht deen uoY"
rewsna ot tuoba saw niawaG "?thgir I mA
,htaerb peed a koot kalitreB ".esoppus
.nac I fi tey onnuD"
"?esuoh eht draw ot tsuj ...saw tahT"
"!sey ,seY" "!?shtnom rof
.uoy otni hteet sih tog eno retfa llit
'.egaruoc' tnaem retnec eht raen eno gib eht wenk eh tub ,tey ssalc taht ni raf yrev nettog t'ndah niawaG .seye
,eromyna ti eveileb t'nseod eh SYAS
.mih ot ...saw taht ,yrroS"
"?uoy fo dloh thguac eh erofeb
meht eganam ot woh uoy gnillet ot dnuora tog ydobon tluaf ruoy ton s'tI
.elbat eht deraelc d'yeht dna
,mih pots ot elba eb t'ndluow eh dna
.did eh nehw eltsirb selkcah s'rotpuretnI eht leef dluoc eh esuaceb ,sepirts
.selohssa t'nera ohw ,sdneirf rehto teg uoY
,ddo detsat spil s'regdab ehT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
".rotsecna ym s'eH
.gniliar kced eht dnuora dnuow sthgil eert fo gnirts eht no dnah eno dial kalitreB
"?enildoolb a teg uoy od woh ,lleW" .t'ndid eh
.esuba yltnias fo edarit eht revo sucof ot gnilggurts ,deknilb
,eno yb eno ,ylidaets denrub neht
.dessarrabme ssel leef mih edam
-dna ,tsehc s'regdab eht ot dnah a desserp eh
.knird gnirewoprevo eht fo pis rehtona koot kalitreB
ylevitroppus dnah a yal dna
.taht ot kcab emoc ll'eW"
.elbuort gnivah detrats uoy nehT"
"?uoy gnitnuah s'revetahw s'erehw ,oS
.emoh kcab serutcip eht morf mih ezingocer I"
".oot meht lennahc ot elba er'uoy
,eson sih hguorht ni
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil
.ecnelis gnol a saw erehT
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dnA
ro htaerb sih ro selcsum sih morf rehtehw ,nepo deppop trihs sih fo tnorf ehT .lluf erom
,sretfar eht ta derewolg kalitreB "!ycreP
.yrellaG yrruFoS
.nepo yrev saw trihs sih dnA
,ti morf rewop tpecca
.wohemos dezinomrah ti
...tsuj yeht ,tey dereffo ev'I seman eht fo yna nekat t'nevah yehT
,lacitcarp ,mlac saw eciov s'kalitreB "?tahw ekiL" ".sgniht
,gnivah saw eh noissucsid eht naht rehtar sucof ot ,gnihtyna
seye sih desolc niawaG
:weiv ylevol a saw ti timda dluow niawaG
.sgniht lufetah ,gnitlusni ,eliv tsom eht gnimaercs
dna socserf hsival gninoissimmoc
,kcen sih no ruf eht evom
".neht ,noitacided tog s'eH" ".nosrep
.lattuber a dah retpurretnI eht esac ni
er'uoY .keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
,kcen sih fo kcab eht no
morf dednecsed eb ot duorp ylsuoivbo llits s'eh dna ,flehs sih no mih tuoba skoob eht lla tog llits s'eh tub
,mih raeh ro ees ot elba eb t'ndluow uoy ,era ew yaw eht detneiro gnieb tuohtiw tahT
,sriahc oitap nedoow dlo ni nwod tas ,kced kcab eht ot tuo enog d'yeht nehT
.dias kalitreB ".ti tog uoY"
.shtnom ni ekahsdnah a sa hcum os nettog t'nevah"
"?gnihsinaB ?sdraw deirt uoy emussA .tihs lleW"
os yas ot tnaw t'ndid eh tub ,desimorp neeb d'eh noitulos fo tros eht drawot gnivom yllanif saw regdab dlo eht ekil dednuos tI
...os ,stnadnecsed dna srotsecna deen uoy
,detcerroc kalitreB ",yaw eno s'tahT"
?scisab eht gnirevoc ton er'uoY"
.scitcat degnahc niawaG
.tey taht timda ot ydaer ton ,on ,tiaW "...s'tI"
"?sdik evah sraey eht revo elpoep fo tol a
.niaga nwod tas dah kalitreB
ekil d'I" ,deplug naiwaG ",hu ,I"
".namahS a sa lufrewop erom worg uoy woh s'taht"
.riahc sih ni kcab depmuls
!tliug ruoy dnatsrednu uoy tsal ta"
.kcab saw dnuohflow eht nehw
".sseug I ,ytilitsoh eht snialpxE"
.gniliar eht no ti tes dah dna
,liar eht no mih ediseb ssalg eht ni tub
?sniatnuom eht pu raf siht teg ot sub dna yrref dna niart yb flah a dna yad a koot tI
etimodos desabed dna citehtap a yb 'dneirf' dellac gnieb ot tnesnoc d'ohw"
".taeper annog ton m'I sgniht ...em dellac s'eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ssalc tpursid dluow eh ,eromyna ydobyna htiw xes evah t'ndluoc I ecnO
taht saw ti ,werg yeht taht t'nsaw ti ,degnahc
,knird neerg luof ylesnetni eht fo tohs rehtona flesmih deruop kalitreB ".on lleH" "?lennahc enildoolb ot ton
.ssalg neerg-elttob kciht hguorht erif eht otni derats niawaG ".dnob fo dnik eno naht erom
eh dna ,cisatsoirepA pu werg daD
,eciov sih fo tuo repmihw hsiyppup a peek t'ndluoc eh "!?mih gnillac m'I"
,reppus devres dah regdab eht oS
,kool ot nrut ot ton
,tnemenota kees dna ecnatneper drawot krow ot nigeb uoy nac neht ylno
,god.ecioVehT ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,derettups god eht
.mih gnillac eno eht er'uoy dna ,tirips nortap ruoy s'eh
.reduol elttil a ekops dna gnicniw nezorf s'niawaG deciton kalitreB "-yb meht ronohsid naht meht deredrum uoy fi retteb eb dluow ti ylurT
.dne no dnats ruf sih dna nettalf srae sih tlef niawaG ".mih
"!?ti t'ndluow ,ECIN dluow taht ,haeY"
.delbmurg kalitreB ".slaitnederc
.ti ees ro raeh t'ndid llitS"
,shpylg erew tsehc sih nwod nettirw dna ,ecrof rehto emos
,s'niawaG naht ruf rekrad ,rehguoR
,eugnot sih nettib d'eh fi sa drow dim deppots eh "-
,ekil ,tuoba stnar tsuj eH"
.neeb evah syawla ,dlrowrehto eht ni yawtrap er'uoy"
",oga seirutnec evif tuoba devil eH"
.sehsid eht enod d'yeht nehT
uoy ot noitcennoc a htiw gnihtemos ro enoemos s'ti si sseug tseB"
"!erom on kaeps ot dereffus eb
,hcamots dna mgarhpaid sih neewteb erehwemos
!trevrep neknurd emos fo ssenisub yna erew ti fi sA"
.dlrowrehto eht ni eot a kcuts tsrif ev'uoy nehw eb ot desoppus ton s'ti erehw pu pop ot gnihtemos rof fo draehnu ton s'ti ,woN
-yas ot tuoba saw eh sgniht eht dna
.afos eht fo kcab eht revo detuohs dna denrut
emoclew er'uoy ,kcab ruoy evah ot tsurt uoy enildoolb ruoy no ydobyna evah t'nod uoy fI"
.redluohs sih revo ecnalg a ksir did niawaG ".haey ,hU" ".egelloc
"'.epoP ecnassianeR' raeh uoy nehw fo kniht uoy gniht fo tros ehT
thgiN neerG ehT .yojne esaelP
,gnihtemos detnaw noitnetta sih taht won tub ,rennid gnivah erew yeht elihw deciton t'ndah niawaG
,dahalaG delrans ",enildoolb on EREW ereht taht dluoW"
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
"!syad gniniamer ruoy lla ekat ti hguoht
.worbeye desserpminu na hguorht knird dehcuotnu s'niawaG ta decnalg
.tserof eht fo llems eht dna regdab eht dna
mih tub kced kcab eht no ydobon saw erehT
,seenk sih no depmuls dna
",uoy taht erus m'I"
".tog uoy noitpo ylno eht tnia enildoolb nwo ruoy"
.dedaf shpylg ehT .dias kalitreB ".ti
,ekas s'kcuf roF"
.serguO'L fo dahalaG .tS s'eman siH"
dnob citsinamahs a dah ydaerla I rotsecna ym s'eh esuaceb gniyas er'uoY"
htaerb mraw leef dluoc niawaG taht hguone esolc ,kalitreB dias
selcsum sih tuoba gnihtemoS
erus yrev edam eH
.neerg yrev erew seye sih dnA
,spil desserp ylthgiT
,epacsdnal ,eert ,tsohg--gnihtyna htiw klat nac emoS
.kO" .dehgis kalitreB ".taht
,dednecsed ssenkrad sa elbisiv erom werg taht woleb nwot eht fo sthgil eht ,tserof peets eht
nis htekaeps taht eh tel dna"
,edistuo tserof eht ,ekomsdoow eht ,ruf sih ,taews sih
.nwod ti deplug niawaG retfa yawa taht desahc tsael ta dah nrub lohocla eht tub
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
?secaps dercas ytisrevinu ehT" .deddon niawaG .dehcterts dna teef sih ot tog kalitreB
,delkcuhc kalitreB ",tahw dnA"
.floWcaM boR yb thgiN neerG ehT
,tpecnoc tcartsba ylluf
niawaG ".evitcele level-roinuj a s'taht kniht I ,hU"
,ht-gnihtemoS eht nrogarA
eseht piks nac uoy
.lufituaeb saw meht hguorht gnirekcilf thgilerif eht
"!ysatsopa s'rehtaf ruoy rof tnemhsinup eht si noisrevrep ruoy deedni spahreP" "?sessalc yna ni
"!timda ot esufer uoy hturt eht ni ecaf ruoy gnibbur efil ruoy fo tser eht dneps ll'I
,regdab eht llems dluoc
,tirips a tem neve reve
"!noitinomda suoethgir ym ot"
.smra s'kalitreB otni drawrof denael dna
"!flesti erutan ot tlusni elbavigrofnu na si htaerb ward tey uoy tcaf eht"
,dias niawaG ".mih ees t'nod I"
s'dahalaG saw raeh dluoc eh lla dna
ruoy ot noitcaer reporp dna thgir s'dlrow larutan eht s'taht esuaceb gnireffus ylno er'uoY
...woh nrael ot evah I ,oS"
.dehtaerb niawaG ".kcuf..."
,enoemos htiw yal
.htaerb peed a deplug god eht
,elbisiv t'nsaw eh hguoht ,delworg dahalaG .tS  "enoyna fi sA"
.won thgin eht ni elbisivni yltsom saw tI .dnoyeb aes eht
,noihsuc afos nrow eht otni raf ylgnisirprus kcab knas niawaG ",onnud I"
"!uoy ot em gnitcennoc"
.ecneirepxe evah t'nseod ohw namahs a htiw tnaw yeht revetahw od nac yeht kniht
.gnihtemos tpurretni rO
"...raey txen kcab eb annog t'nsaw ylbaborp I ecnis ,tniop hcum ees t'ndid I dna detrats siht neht
!rehtom roop ruoy dna rehtaf ruoy emahs
ni saw eh lleh cibohpomoh revetahw ni kcuts eb llits d'eh
drawrof denael kalitreB
.niaga trihs sih nottub ot rehtob t'ndid eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
gnidaerd neeb d'eh noitseuq eht saw erehT
"?ti ekil uoy d'woh ,lleW"
,nwod ssalg ytpme sih tes regdab ehT ".ecneirepxe
.meht gnoma gnidih eb ot gniog saw rosseforp eht fi sa
s'erehT .namahS a sa worg uoy"
.ssalg deniats neerg erew srood ecalperif eht dna ,elit neerg fo edam saw edisni htraeh ehT
".tcatnoc edam uoy dias uoY .nortap ruoY"
,oot s'moM ,ylimaf s'daD ym lla hcum ytterp"
.deliaf dna ,llams dnuos ot ton deirt niawaG ".haey ,pleh dluoc ohw enoemos wenk eh dias larGeD rosseforP"
.esuoh eht dnuora lla neerg tfos emas eht htiw til erew yeht llit
?thgir ,oreteh er'uoy fi krow t'nseod ti tahT
,deddon naiwaG ",haeY"
,dnal ym no ,esuoh ym ni
.srae sih ot tfil on
".won ereh eb t'ndluow uoy
.elpoep fo snoillim gniredrum sa emas eht si nemow htiw gnipeels ton woh
.flesmih ti yas emoc nac eh
,tsopmoc ecirouqil neerg ekil detsat llits knird ehT  ".ti barg ll'I
".senildoolb tuoba klat s'teL .yawynA
",tiaW" "?sdik evah annog er'yeht fi
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daeR
,thgit tiS" .deddon niawaG
"?hcruhc dlo eht morf s'eh oS"
,ekil tlef ti rae
,yllanretni demuf god eht ,gnihton ta gnikool saw nam dlo siht elihW
sih sa thgil neerg tfos emas eht htiw gniremmihs
.ti ekam nac I sa eruces sa eb dluohs ,thgirlA"
.dellif sgnul sih sa nwod dellup tug sih
.slaitnederc s'ycreP gninoitseuq ylsuoires saw I uoy llet em tel esuaceb ,raeh ot dooG"
.noihsuc riahc eht tsniaga daeherof sih
niawaG ".skrow ti woh tsuj"
.taht ta ,sehtolc ereves dlO
.sehtolc ereves ,ralloc lacirelc
-fo kcatta rehtona rof gnitiaw slaoc toh no gnittis saw eh
,afos hsulp deroloc-enip eht fo kcab eht revo trihs sih dessot dah kalitreB
ro krow t'ndid esoht dnA
.seye eht ni mih dekool dna
.nettirw s'eh skoob ynam woh erac t'nod
hgis a devaeh niawaG
.deneppah tahw s'taht sseug d'I
elgnit ti leef dluoc niawaG ,esolc ylsuolirep dna wol saw eciov s'kalitreB ".sruoy ot yeht dna ,yllautirips
,ria ytpme eht ta wap evisired a devaw eh ",wonk uoy
.rotpurretnI eht daerd ot denrael d'eh sa hcum sa tsomla
.smrotsrednuht htiw od ot gnihtemos ...er'yeht ,hO"
,noitadarged sih ni flesruoy revoc
,liat sih ot lruc oN
.erofeb mih deppots reven dah taht tub ,won thgir ,nees eb ot erehwon saw dnuohflow ehT
wohs emag a no ezirp a sa mih gnitneserp fi sa god deye-yrgnuh eht ot derutseg eh ",emos dna
hcihw htaerb sih no knird egnarts eht neve dna
.deksa kalitreB
,ebyam ,stirips fo stros llA
,hu ,s'regdab eht ta kool ot ton tseb sih gniod saw niawaG dna
,saw ti tahw wonk ot tnaw t'ndid eh
.ereht tniop a dah eH ".shtnom
nalp s'kalitreB rehtehw tuo dnif ot
?thgir ,hguoht ,namahs a er'uoy yhw s'taht swonk eH"
".peels ot deirt I revenehw ot no devom eh nehT
.yteixna eht hguorht sucof flesmih ekam ot wap eno htiw rae yppolf sih debburcs niawaG ",eh ,on ,oN"
uoY" "!?xes evah ot deen I gniyas er'uoy"
.dlog naht rehtar deroloc dum
ylneddus eb ot demees yeht
,tey gnilennahc enildoolb revo neeb uoY"
raeH" ,ecnelis eht ekorb yllanif kalitreB ",oS"
s'niawaG otni yltcerid ,retpurretnI eht deyab ",etimodos tnatnepernu yhtliF"
,tsrif reppus evah d'yeht detsisni dah kalitreB .sniatnuom eht ni pu neerg dellems ria ehT
niawaG ".yug a htiw saw I llit detiaw tsuj eh tsrif tA"
,edis ot edis morf decnalg dna ,ylsuoicipsus ,dekcoc rae na dah regdab eht ",oN"
...ot detcartta m'I taht ekil t'nseod eH"
,snis ruoy fo htped eht tpecca dna gnitsiser potS
ev'yeht erofeb seidob rieht fo tuo tcejorp nac emos
".pu tuhs mih ekam yehT
sseldrow ,sseltneler
tsrif od elpoep od"
eht ta rehposolihp dna naigoloeht a saw eh" ,denialpxe eh
.yawa knarhs dna sredluohs sih dehcnuh niawaG nehw deppots tub
.deen uoy fi elttil a ydob ruoy revo ekat ti tel neve ,seod ti yaw eht sgniht ecneirepxe
"?huh ,taht niod em ekil t'ndid eH"
.owt fo eno trap ,floWcaM boR yb
,sdraw ym hguorht thgir teg ot elba saw eh yhw s'tahT"
,morf nellaf d'eh riahc oitap eht thgir ot gnilbmuf t'nerew god eht fi sa deklat regdab ehT ".hguoht ,eveis a hguorht retaw ekil sdraw eht hguorht thgir og ti tleF
",gniht doog a s'ti nehT" ".edis sih ekat"
.era stirips erehw s'tahT
.epoh tneitapmi tuo trulb ot ton gniyrt ,pil sih tib niawaG
dediced niawaG hcihw
,d'yeht ,enildoolb ym no esle ydobyna lennahc ot deirt I fi ,deirrow eb d'I
,ecaf s'god eht hcuot ot dehcaer regdab ehT ".uoy
.esolc yrev ylneddus saw kalitreB ".tpurretni
.ecnatsid eht otni ffo dezag tsuj kalitreB elihw ytinrete na ekil tlef tahw rof tas d'yeht neht dnA
.erif eht rof doow erom gnitteg tuoba gniklat erew eh fi sa
.rehtona ro dnob adnik eno rof tnelat a teg snamahs emos ylsuoivbo oS
"!ssenlarutannu detsiwt
,mih ot resolc tis ot tnaw t'nod uoy fi sa kool ot gniyrt ,gnikniht er'uoy tahw yltcaxe wonk I
,ot dedeen eh naht afos eht no resolc tas kalitreB
.pu emoc dluow tI
"?namahS a saw I wenk I erofeb nevE ?dahalaG .tS ot
.tog s'ytisrevinu eht snoitarcesnoc dna stnemhsinab revetahw hguorht
,os gniyas ym ot noitcaer fo kcal ruoy morf dnA"