mih ta debbats cennef retrohs eht dna dehsalf revlis gnihtemos
”.nwo sih dedda sohteS
.ediw tog seye s’hateehc eht dna
.roolf eht ot ylsselmrah gnillaf epor eht
”.nekat neeb ecnis gnol sah ti
deddon lakcaj ehT
.selacs eht gnihctaw
.ti ot revo deklaw dna rood delaes eht ot detniop lakcaj ehT
,debircsni saw decalp dah sohteS
,traeh s’usrI dleh eh ti nI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”,mih tae tsuj ot gnipoh saw I“
.pmal lio eht nwod gnittup
rehtaef eht rof dehcaer neht eH
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
.htuom reh ni hteet gnol eht lla gniwohs ,dehgual timmA
…snoilliM swollawS ohW goD eht
.sgnaf desopxe reh fo eno gnikcil eugnot reh
dnuorg eht no gniyl saw ohw
.derednop dog lakcaj ehT
,cennef trohs eht dias
,etihw saw rehtaef ehT
.emoc ton did yehT“
,edalb eht ot htgnerts fo drow derepsihw a htiW
,ylwols deddon usrI
,pmal lio dna ffats sih gniyrraC
.detnioppasid dekool aremihc ehT
”,uoy dniheb thgir eb ll’I .oG“
ak sih niatsus ot tnaem erew taht sgniht eht fo enon tub
”.dessap snoitareneg eht sa denekaew evah tsum lleps ehT“
”?gnissim slleps eht fo tser eht t’nerA“
.rettalp rehto eht no ti decalp dna
,snoitareneg ynam hguorht III sohteS devres dah ylimaf siH
,uraA ot og tonnac uoy ,slleps eht tuohtiw ta’uD otni ssap dluoc uoy fi nevE“
,srae dna daeh devruc a htiw retpecs a deirrac eh dnah eno nI
,xof rehto eht dias ”,ffo epor siht tuc em tel ,haeY“
,edistuo morf ni tperc thgil tsetniaf eht ylnO
og dluoc I .spahreP“
.ta’uD otni dessap yeht ylekilnu si ti os ,em ot emoc ton did yehT“
,tuo sdoog eht gnikat retfa slaes eht decalper enoemoS“
”?evila llits stnerap ruoy erA .tebeN“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.emit gnol a ni yenruoj eht edam sah eno on ,dias I sA“
.rehtom ym si tebeN“
rettiwt no gnitirw sih tuoba erom dnif nac uoY
.feilebsid ni dias hateehc eht
”.sparcs no evil ot evah regnol on ll’eW
”?bmot ytpme na dedraug evah srotsecna yM“
.ti ot pu deklaw usrI yltnatiseH
”.tey denepo neeb s’ti fi rednow I .thgir erew uoY“
”.dlo sraey fo sdnasuoht si bmot sihT ?tahW“ ”.hoarahP
.ytud lartsecna sih morf kcab knirhs ot ydaer tuoba ton saw eh dna
,rebmahc lairub eht ,yrusaert ehT .erab deppirts moor hcae ,enog saw ereht
”naidrauG bmoT ehT“
.pu ti dekcip dna roolf eht no yal llits hsepohk eht erehw ot revo deklaw sibunA .enog saw dna
.derevaw selacs eht fo ecnalab eht ekops eh sA .usrI derepsihw
,yhtrow era uoy fI
”naidrauG bmoT ehT“ saw sihT
.nekowa dah sohteS nehw morf esab eht ffo yltrap gnignah dil sti
”…er’uoy dna ,daed m’I“
,erofeb deciton reven d’eh
.llaw eht ssorca dnah a decart eH
”?tnaw uoy tahw taht sI
.enog erew roolf rebmahcetna eht derevoc taht dnas dna tsud ehT
hsepohk eht htiw llaw eht kcurts eh
.eno rellat eht dias
.hoarahP eht sevres ylimaf yM“
.usrI deksa ”?ti si tahW“
,ssenkrad eht ni rallip eht dniheb dehcuorc usrI
.od ton dluohs uoy sgniht owt-ytrof ehT“ ”?tahw ehT“
”naidrauG bmoT ehT“:yojne esaelP
efiw sih fo noitciped elgnis a ees ton od I
traeh s’usrI rof dehcaer neht eH
,elidocorc a fo daeh eht htiw erutaerc A
.redluohs eht ni kcurts saw eh sa ynoga ni tuo deirc ohw cennef rellat eht no nwod edalb eht thguorb usrI
.taht daer t’nac I“
.thgin ta bmot eht ot egalliv eht morf klaw I“
,yltnatcepxe dnuora dekool lakcaj ehT
”.rebmemer t’nod I“ .llef srae siH
.llaw eht no gnitniap dedaf eht ssorca deraems doolb sih
hateehc eht ot kcab deklaw sibunA dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.kcab srae ,usrI deksa
,deveileb yllaer ton d’eH
.noitom gnioohs a edam lakcaj eht tub
.nwod deppit hcihw ,rettalp gnignah eno no
neeb evah dluohs taht gnihtyrevE .ytpme saw bmot eht edisnI .denworf sibunA .dewollof hateehc eht dna
,detelpmoc neeb dah bmot eht taht dewohs sllaw eht gnirevoc efil s’sohteS gnitciped
”.erew uoy ohw wonk ot deen I tsrif tub ,traeh ruoy hgiew lliw eW“ ”?em dnA“
.delrans usrI
,timmA detseggus ”,uoy eerf syawla nac I“ .usrI deksa
”.sohteS degduj I ekil tsuJ“
”,shoarahp eht fo eno ot degnoleb siht eveileb I
,ylimaf eht hguorht nwod edalb eht gnissap
,rood eht tsniaga nwod deppils dna
.kcab delbmuts usrI dna
.delbmurc ylkciuq eh tub
,flesmih dniheb gnihsal liat
.thgil eht ni yks thgin eht ekil tsomla dekool ti dna
,sbir sih neewteb thgir knus reggad s’cennef ehT
”?ton ti saw ,od ot hguoht ytud ruoy saw tahT“ .desuap sibunA
,pu dekcab cennef eht sA
”.ytud ym gnillifluf ,III sohteS fo bmot eht nI“
delims lakcaj ehT
.hcamots sih hguorht raet reggad eht tlef eh
.deggurhs lakcaj ehT
.emit yb won nettogrof eb dluow sohteS
.yawrood eht drawot gnitniop ,dias sibunA
.dnuora denrut lakcaj ehT
.ereh eb dluow siht wenk I .thgir saw I“
.mih revo doots ssenkrad ni dekaolc erugif a daetsni dna
,tneserp saw sugahpocras a ylnO .tneserp erew
.oga sraey wef a deid htob yehT .oN“
.bmot eht fo rood delaes eht dna
”.ti draug ot ereh emoc I
,bmot sih fo sllaw eht no debircsni slleps eht fo ynam evah ot mees t’nseod eH
.timmA dias ”,slleps eht s’tI“
.degduj eb llahs uoy dna ,uoy egduj ot ytud ym si tI .su sevig
,hsepohk sih pu gnitfil
.thgil fo latrop eht ot deklaw neht sibunA ,gnilimS
.sdeer fo dleif eht
.depsar ehs ”,ak s’enoemos netae evah I ecnis gnol oot neeb sah tI“
selacs eht ylwolS
”.pirt siht ekam ot dednetni reven eh esuaceb
.hcamots sih no rehto eht dna
.hguone nees d’eH
.meht thguat reven erew uoy fi snoissefnoc eht od ot uoy ksa tonnac I“
.mih dniheb yltnelis gnihsal liat sih
”.htaed ni traeh sih nwod dehgiew efil ni sdeed siH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.won ti fo deen on sah eH .daeD eht fo kooB s’sohteS worrob lliw eW“
.ereh emac srotsecna ym lla toN“
,roolf eht tih cennef ehT .dereggats eh sa hsepohk eht
.ekirts ot ydaer drows-elkcis eht htiw drawrof gnipeerc
”.yenruoj eht etelpmoc uoY“ ”?tahw won tub“
”.hguone esir ton did eliN eht nehw deliaf sporc ruo dna ylimaf roop a era eW
.pu ekops timmA ”?evael I naC“
”.deid yeht nehw erehwesle tnew yeht ylekil si tI
,tsael ta sraey dnasuoht A
.ti llif ot detrats dnas sa
deggas hateehc ehT ”.yhtrow
.kcab dennip srae
,denworf lakcaj ehT
bmot eht dewollaws ssenkrad dna
,sgnitniap dedaf ,nrow fo daetsnI
”?eid uoy did erehW“
oppih a fo sgel dna ,noil a fo tsehc dna enam eht
,efil ym uoy llet nac I“
,etunim a rof deredisnoc dog ehT
.moor eht ni deraeppa dah stnecca nedlog htiw selacs kcalb egral fo tes a
,srebbor bmot erew owt esehT
,edis eht ot depmuls dna
.sibunA deksa usrI ”?uoy htiw
”?uoy rof slleps eht eraperp ton did ylimaf ruoY“
.seitrebil niatrec ekat nac I tub ,dlrowrednu eht delur I ecnis emit gnol a neeb sah tI“ .derednop eh ”?eM“
.lakcaj eht ekops ”,siht enod evah ew ecnis ega na neeb sah tI .timmA ,won emoc
.knalf sih ni dnuow eht tsniaga
.yaw evag ti ecrofnier ot desu d’eh cigam eht dna drows-elkcis eht deppord eh ,deifsitaS
.ereh yenruoj eht ,seY“
”?eman ruoy si tahW“
”.ti dnefed ot ytud ym si tI“
.tnelis saw hateehc ehT
,kcab hsepohk eht deknay hateehc eht sA
,usrI derepsihw ”,uoy knahT“
,hateehc eht ot pu deklaw dna
.eman doog a si tI
”?rehtaf dna rehtom ruoy era ohW“ .derednop eH
,xof eht kcurts eh sA
”?ecalp siht ot ylimaf ym dnuob eh dias uoY“
ot uoy fo doog si tI“ .selacs eht fo edis eno ot detiaw
”,yenruoj siht edam sah enoemos ecnis emit gnol ,gnol a neeb sah tI“
.eno retrohs eht ,scennef eht fo eno dias
”?eman ruoy si tahW“
,ylbitpecrepmi tsomlA
.timmA ot mih deef ot dah I dna ,hguoht yvaeh oot saw luos siH
gnirpsyaD seyEthgiN yb
.drawrof degnul usrI
.dnabtsiaw sih otni dekcut ,gniyrrac neeb dah eh rehtaef a tuo dellup neht dna selacs eht dekcehc sibunA sa
”.sibunA droL ,gnihton rof ereh uoy thguorb gnivah rof seigolopa yM“
”!rehtorb ym dellik uoy dnA“
.enog erew sdnuow siH
”?yvaeh oot traeh ym sI“ .gnikniht
uoy erA .uoy rof od neht nac I tahw fo kniht lliw I
,tac eht deksa ”?yenruoJ“
.devlossid ti dna llaw retsalp eht dehcuot sibunA
.tnemom a rof deredisnoc erugif krad ehT
.pu tog hateehc eht ,no gniog saw tahw fo erusnU ”.dnats woN
.ylimaf rooN eht fo esoht ot dellac taht eno eht
.emac eh ecnis seirutnec neeb sah tI
.rebmemer t’ndluoc eH ”…si eman ym tub
”?usrI si eman ym rebmemer em pleh ot gniog taht si woH
,sterceS fo retsaM ,srenretseW eht fo tsomeroF“
.traeh ruoy hgiew ot ereh ma I dna
.usrI deremmats ”?sey …I“ ”?ydaer
.eciov peed a denotni
slleps eht fo eno erehw llaw eht ot revo tnew eH
.gnidaer ylluferac ,llaw eht ssorca sdnah sih decart sibunA .usrI deksa
.pmal lio eht nwod gnittes ,selacs eht ot revo deklaw lakcaj ehT
?usrI .swonk dnim ehT“
.gnihtolc tresed gnittif esool ni desserd erew htoB
”,tcatni si laes yalc eht tub ,yltnecer tuo gud saw ti ekil skool yawecnartne ehT .yas ot draH“
,em yb degduj eb dluow ereh yal ohw enoyna taht os ti edam eH“
”!bmot ym dekcatta uoY“ .xof eht delrans
ta’aM hturt fo rehtaef eht htiw traeh ruoy hgiew ot selacs eht erofeb dnats uoy ,filA dna tebeN fo nos ,usrI“
,desaeler laes ehT
.thgil fo yawrood eht ta deknilb usrI
.tnemom a rof tnelis saw erugif krad ehT
”?gnissim erew slleps eht thguoht I“
.ydaer ton llits saw eh tey dna
”.yenruoj eht etelpmoc ot elba eb reven lliw uoY
.erofeb egalliv eht ni uoy nees ev’I ,tiaW“
.denrut lakcaj ehT
.mih rebmemer I ,sey hA“
.hserf dna thgirb erew gniliec dna sllaw detniap ylhcir eht
”?ereh deppart m’I ,oS“
.rebmemer t’ndluoc eH
cennef eht derettups ”…dratsaB“
,dnuow eht hcnuats ot deirt ylbeef cennef rellat ehT
.floW-pilS htiw slangiS tnedissiD ygolohtna eht detide eh dna
,hsepohk eht gniws ot detrats eh sa tsuJ
.tsehc s’cennef eht ssorca edalb eht gnignirb ,niaga gnuws dna pag eht desolc eH
bmot eht fo llaw eht ot revo delbmuts eH
.ecalp siht ot ylimaf ruoy dnuob eh dna
eman sih drocer ton dluoc eh dias htohT
.cennef rellams eht delrans
.llaw eht morf deppihc neeb dah s’rooN eht fo eman eht litnu
,spmal elpitlum yb til won saw moor ehT
scihpylgoreih eht deiduts yeht sa gniklat erew scennef ehT
ngised dlog dna eulb lufituaeb a dah gniliec ehT
eeffochtiwflow@ ta
.ffo deliart hateehc eht
.kcab dnah sih dellup dna gnihtemos derepsihw eH
,uoy tsniaga ssentiw raeb ton seod traeh ruoy ,revewoH
”.ta’uD gniretne fo yhtrow ton saw eH
.thgil eht hguorht dehsinav ehS
,taeH dna GNAF ekil seigolohtna ni deraeppa sah krow ’seyEthgiN
rentrap sih ta decnalg cennef trohs ehT
.moc.gnirpsyad-
.delbmuts eh ”…si eman yM“
deppord eh dna
”.sdeen sih tius ot deretla meht dah evah tsum sohteS“
.ruf wolley sih niats ot sregnif sih dnuora dezoo doolB
scihpylgoreih dna serutcip thgirb ehT
,etelpmoc ylneddus tlef eH
.lleps eht ta decnalg hateehc ehT
,dah egalliv eht ni enoyna naht redlo eman a mih nevig d’yehT
.eman sih tub ereht saw gnihtyrevE
.bmot eht ni thgilpmal ot ekowa eH   #   .daed
.doolb fo loop tnaig a ni
.dewollof llits ylimaf sih snoitidart eht
.edis eht ot gnillor
.meht dellif elttab fo segamI
.gnihtemos snaem taht uoy ot enigami I tub ,flesym ekil enoemos ot sselgninaem tib a steg emiT .kniht I
uoy meed I .eil ot snoitaraperp on edam evah uoy dna
.yenruoj siht rof noitaraperp yna detelpmoc ton sah usrI
si yrots s’yadot dna
,III sohteS fo ytreporp eht si sihT“
denediw seye s’hateehc ehT
.hcamots sih gnola tlef eH
,sllaw eht dennacs eH
dnah eerf sih gnisserp ,usrI taps
.ylimaf sih fo ytud eht gniod yb ti deronoh eh dna
.ylsuovren hateehc eht deksa
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ruf dettops s’usrI ni ssentew ykcits gniworg a saw erehT
”.ereh naht retteb eb dluow tI“ .deddon usrI
”?srehto eht era erehw ,timmA”
.derettahs edalb ehT
.yaw ruoy no uoy dnes tonnac I“
.rewop taerg dedleiw ti llet dluoc eh ,usrI ot nevE
”.neeb reven evah retsis dna rehtorb yM
,seye sih desolc hateehc ehT
,syaw dlo eht tuoba mih dlot dah rehtom siH
.cennef eht drawot gnipael ,usrI delley
.gnilddapkcab erofeb
.ylimaf rooN eht morf era uoY
.flesruoy ot peek uoY
ti decalp sibunA sa ti ta erats ylno dluoc hateehc ehT
,rallip eht dniheb morf tuo deppets usrI
.moor eht ni esle eno on saw ereht tub
”.won ak ruoy hgiew llahs ew ,emoC
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
?yas eh dluoc esle tahW
.pu ti dekcip dna
”.bmot siht tcetorp ot dellac eb dluow yeht ,evoba dlrow eht ni devil enildoolb ’srehtaferof ruoy sa gnol sA .seY“
,mra sih fo kcorc eht ni ffats eht gnildarC
”,aR-fo-traeH-eht-seificaP-ohW-eH
;ssenkrad ni dekaolc ton saw mih erofeb erugif ehT
”,neht ssol rieht ,lleW“
.sdeed sih ylno dna sdeed sih htiw sllaw eseht dellif eH
,sibunA dias ”,tsrif sgniht tsriF“ .deksa ursI
.denrut dna rae na dekcilf cennef retrohs eht
.pmal lio na deirrac eh rehto eht ni elihw
”?ytpme eb ot desoppus ti sI“
.slleps ehT“ ”?sllepS“
.mih no detnilg dloG
,bmot eht dnuora deklaw sibunA ”.oN“
.rae na ta dehctarcs cennef rellat ehT
.derebmemer eb ot detnaw ohw nam a ylsuoivbo saw eH
.kcalb ni erugif eht detaeper
.dekcilf srae s’cennef ehT
”.ta’uD otni ssap tonnac uoy ,slleps eht tuohtiw ,revewoH
.ak sih kcab usrI gnivig
.rebmahcetna eht hguorht swodahs gnol tsac taht pmal lio na gniyrrac bmot eht deretne dah
.ecalp siht dnefed ot boj sih saw ti dna
.yenruoj eht etelpmoc t’nac uoy slleps eht tuohtiW
,eeffoc rof tnahcnep a htiw flow A
”.yhtrow si eh fi ees ew tsriF“
.lakcaj eht dias ”,oN“
,dnuora denrut eH
”,bmot siht fo esnefed ni nem owt dellik I“
.nam niav a saw sohteS“
redluohs sih no dnah eno decalp dna
.dessap eh sa yltnetni dehctaw
.hcir eb ll’ew ,ereh ni erusaert eht htiW“
.ria eht ni taolf ot tsomla demees dna
.roolf enots eht no gnihguoc yal eh sa
”?snoissefnoc evitagen owt-ytrof eht wonk uoy oD“
”.yademos rehtona htiw dedrawer eb ll’ew spahrep ,llew hO“
.sibunA dias ”,kniht em teL“
”.eman ruoy sdrocer htohT sselnu uoy tpecca ton lliw sirisO
.nwod dna pu decnalg dna deppots lakcaj ehT
.rebmahcetna s’bmot eht ot kcab usrI gnidael
.thgil eht ni enohs edalb ehT
.daeh sih koohs sibunA ”?nehT“
”?ereh gniod uoy era tahW
.taht tsuj naht erom s’tI“
”.ereh thgir si eman sih rebmemer ot eno eht tub
”.no seog tsil ehT .sdog eht esruc toN .nemow dna nem yals toN .laets toN .ecneloiv htiw yrebbor timmoc toN
”?ereh teg uoy did woH
.scihpylgoreih emos ta detniop lakcaj ehT
seyethgin//:sptth ,etisbew sih tuo kcehc ro
.rallip eht morf ffo dehsup timmA
.noitatnacni na ekops dna laes yalc eht rof dehcaer eh
”.mih yarteb traeh sih did ylkciuq os tub
.noertaP sih no deraeppa hcihw
.ytpme lla erew ,moor mrots eht neve
.aremihc elidocorc eht detaeper ”,ti t’nsi ,slleps eht s’tI“
.erofeb esoht dna ,stnerapdnarg sih dna ,stnerap sih fo ytud eht dewollof d’eh tub
.seye sih sucof dna yrt ot gniknilb
.ereh ni stnerap fo
.sllaw eht revo dekool dna pu pmal lio eht dleh eH
,tsehc sih no dnah sih decalp dna
,daed deedni era uoy ,sey tub ,no dna no og seltit ehT
.nials d’eh cennef tsrif eht morf doolb eht fo loop eht denioj ylkciuq doolb sih tub ,ytud sih enod d’eH
.srae eninac llat htiw ,kcalb hctip saw eh
”!dnif ruo si sihT“
”.doomhaM fo nos filA deirram ehS
.rebmemer regnol on dluoc eh eman A
,su swohs ta’aM tahw fo hturt eht taehc dluoc eh thguoht eh sirbuh sih saw taerg oS
.ti no gniht ylno eht saw rehtaef eht ecnis detlit selacs eht
,bmot eht ni srallip eht fo eno tsniaga gninael
gnihctaw saw hateehc eht scennef owt eht tub
.desolc bmot eht ot srood eht dnuob taht epor eht gnitcepsni
”.gnihton htiw mih deirub yeht ro
,ereh daeD eht fo kooB a saw ereht fI
.deifsitas deddon dog ehT .tuo deneve
dedaf moor eht ni thgil eht lla ,tfel eh sA
.tcejbo ton dluow sirisO
.ecnesse efil s’usrI htiw taeb ti ylwolS .ak sih
,enog erew scennef eht fo seidob ehT
.rebmahcetna eht ni scihpylgoreih eht gnitcepsni
”.ereh yna egduj ot saw I esuaceb em ot emac uoY“
thgil eht hguorht deklaw hateehc ehT
.degdod ylisae cennef eht dna ,ediw tnew gniws siH
.emit gnol yrev ,yrev a rof ,os yltnerappA“
timmA dna ,sibunA dewollof hateehc ehT
bmot eht deretne eh
.llaw raf eht ni deraeppa taht thgil fo rood a drawot meht tsap gniklaw ,dias ehs
.llaw eht ot pu deklaw hateehc ehT
,yltneitap detiaw ehS
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
.yvaeh oot saw ak sih yhw si siht esnes I“
.won ereh emoc dluow eno oN
.noitpircsni llams a ta deppots lakcaj eht litnu ,gnola gniklaw
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN ecalperif-eht-fo-dneirf yb