,dnik ym ekil ylralucitrap ton seod eripmE ehT
.klof tac eht htiw hcum tcaretni ton od eW“
.ssendam fo egrev eht no ylurt dekool eh won ,erofeb dezarc dekool dah knom eht fI
,denniks yltrepxe dna thgin eht fo teiuq eht ni nials
.efil ot dekraps nwo rieht fo deen a ,tsaerb rieht nihtiw dna
,yrarbil eht otni kcab slairetam fo sdaol gniluah nageb keleB dna
secnarussaer eltneg gnirrup erofeb
,llew…won dna ,emit tsal eht rof detfihs sah eH
”.htron og lliw uoy won dnA“
.eramthgin gnisaecnu ni klaw ,revewoh ,emoS
.sdrow s’koob eht eveilebnu ot flesmeht ecrof ton dluoc yehT
”.kaeps skoob ruo hcihw fo snomed emas esoht neve spahreP
,yrotcefer eht ni era segaw ruoY
,skoob eht ssorca kcab yaw rieht decart ,detatiseh yehT
.meht dniheb yal liat rieht tel dna ,pac rieht devomer ,leed rieht tuo dehtooms yehT
.eno gnuoy ,tser tsum I…tsum I“
.gnidnats neeb dah eh hcihw yb nretcel a fo egde eht deppirg knom dlo ehT
.rekihhctiH flowereW
— neppah dluow elbirret gnihtemos rehtie
.eramthgin a ni gnivil
yrarbil eht gnidaol-er fo ksat a saw ti ,no neht morF
.stnerrot elbaroxeni ni
.detuohs yeht ”!knom dlo ehT“
,ecnelis dezinoga
tekram ta sniag laer rieht lles ot
,skcor eht ni neddih dah yeht kcap a otni yawa dedlof edih dna taem deird eht
,ediwrevo seye sih
.thguac reven erew yehT
.stirips dekciw ro snomed emoceb yehT
.sdrow ym daer uoy ,keleB“ ”?tegrof-
,thgiarts dna ffits
,riah s’ydal eht dehsurb
”!yrarbil eht ni nellaf sah eH“
”?doof ruo tae uoy naC
.ria eht ni s’keleB htiw dehsalc sdrow detlits yllauqe s’knom ehT ”.sruoy won si tI
.gnivirts dna tnetnI
.rednop ot knom eht rof aedi na fo sgninnigeb eht
,eurt yllohw reven
”.ti nopu llef dna dneirf a morf drows a deggeb eh os
ylimaf llams a htiw nosaes gniraehs gnirud dekrow dah yehT
.yllairotaripsnoc ni denael tac eht ”,llew
”?naem uoy did tahW
”.keleB ,keleB ,keleB“
.depsag yeht ”,retfird a ma I…I“
,eno gnuoy ,esaelP“
,meht dnuora flesti depparw hturt ehT
thgit oot elttil a spahrep dehcterts niks nworb siH .deticxE
?morf emoc yeht dah erehW
.won uoy htiw ma I .rebmemer uoY
llew tfihs ton od yeht
mraw ot nageb koob eht ,ylneddus dna
.sehsitef ro seutats llams ot dnuob nomed a ro ,esruc A
,noitcerid rehtona ni ylneddus noitasrevnoc eht dellup keleB ,revewoh ,dnopser dluoc eh erofeB
erif yrd ,llams a fo thgil edur eht yb saw ti dna
.dnuora delrihw dna detloj yehT ”.keleB“
.eye sih ni maelg egnarts a
,yrotimrod eht ni toc a htiw uoy edivorp ot yppah era ew tub
,looc tsuj ton saw tI
;snroh fo tsalb tnatsid a dednuos ereht
.flehs eht morf emulov dnuob-rehtael eht werd ylluferac neht
draob eht no seceip eht gnoma
— noitadnemmocer gniwolg a dna snioc ni mus emosdnah a htiw yawa emoc dna
,ereh emit ruoy rof uoy yap ot elba eb lliw ew ,ksat eht fo noitelpmoc nO
.serutcirts ruo fo stimil eht nihtiw
tnemesuma ni meht dniheb dekcot-kcit liat s’keleB ”?kahzroO gnuoy ,yas yeht sa lufdaerd sa eh saW
,boj eht no teiuq dna ,gnikrow drah erew yehT
dah sknom eht gnillif eht fo sllab demaets htiw pu llif dluow yeht neht dna
ragus fo pmul llams a gniraps
elbaliava si gnitirw reH
.raelc saw txet eht fo gninaem ehT
.detpecca slaed dna niagrab dna eciohc fo rewop fo ffihw dirca na ,nemo fo gnat a
,htuom rieht otni llabtaem a deppop yehT
,koob eht ta nwod dekool keleB ,kcurtsbmuD
,htuom rieht ni ylio tlef yehT .larutannu
detelpmoc neeb dah gnigolatac ehT
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,wol dewob keleB ”.egnahcxe ni
.reh fo tseb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
,meht dnuora sdworc eht gnitekcopkcip yb mus regral raf a dna
“–nekatsim saw eh fI
robal ruoy rof egnahcxe ni uoy rof edivorp ot nac ew tahw od lliw eW
kcap rieht morf koob eht evomer ot dediced yeht yhw wonk ylthgir ton did yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,kcap rieht deredluohs
,ekawa tonnac luos rieht ,sevil nwo rieht ekat yeht dluohs tuB“
,detnalp saw dees ehT .erehT
,elbissop fi deriaper dna ,denaelc
…tac gnuoy dnik siht rof tfig a spahreP
.dehsinif saw krow eht ,retal syad eerhT
.deirc dna demaercs ehs sa rae s’ydal eht otni
,gnihtemos dedeen tI
.segaw s’eno htiw og ot tfig a tsuj dnoyeb slaeD
,eert a dluow sa gnillaf
.stroffe ym rof egnahcxe ni siht em dereffo eH“
,wob das a ro evaw dnik a htiw
;serutnevda rieht fo seirots gnillet dna pu gninepo netfo
.depsar knom dlo eht
.edam neeb sah laed ehT“
— detfihs yeht emit yreve rebmemer dluow yehT
”efil ym ni egdelwonk hcus yb dednuorrus neeb reven evah I“
.revoc eht nepo dna
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.kahzroO gnuoy ,uoy knahT“
.ylteiuq dekrow dna
,ruf yarg taht htaeneb gnorts ylevitpeced ,hguone hsiyob dna ,efiwdim a eb ot hguone eninimef dna thgils saw ohw eno eht
.klof tac fo dnof ton saw eripmE ehT
”.pu ekaw ylurt yeht nehw si taht ,eid yeht nehw ,spahreP
,regral a dna
”?drol ,reffo ot epoh ylbissop I dluoc tahW
.ereh yats ruoy gnirud yrotcefer eht ta emoclew eb lliw uoy dna
.hgis detnetnoc a sa emac sdrow ehT
,ti fo thgiew dloc eht ot desu gniworg erew yeht dna
,llorcs yreve nwod ekat tsum ew sraey evif yrevE“
.evaeL“ “–I tuB ?evaeL“
,detcepsni eb dluow yeht erehw
”,ereh krow ot ecnahc eht rof dna
koob siht tpecca uoy dluow
.nioc elpmis naht
,tuat saw niks siH
,sluos dnik evah htroN eht ni emos tub
.tor fo sngis dna hsifrevlis rof gnikcehc
,keleB dnuora neht ,rehto hcae dnuora deniwt
.no eye rieht dah yeht skoob rehto erew erehT .deknilb tac ehT
.esiar selkcah rieht
apmast fo llab a gnillor elihw desuap knom ehT
,sllorcs fo noitcerid eht ,krow fo keew a retfA
.lwa enif a em detfig eh tub ,hcum em yap ton dluoc eH“
.esnet dnoyeb saw noisserpxe siH
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
,flesmeht ot tpek yehT
,eciov a fo noitseggus eht ylno spahrep ro repsihw a ro ohce na
egdelwonk fo emot llams siht tpecca dluow uoy fi deronoh eb dluow I ,esaelP“
oitap a ot meht ekat dna sgur eht pu llor dluow yeht ,noonretfa eht nI
eerf rof daer ro esahcrup ot skoob dna ,smeop
”.laed a dehcaer owt uoy ees I“
dna etilop ylgniliafnu erew yeht ,saw ti sA
,peehs eritne na fo tnemyap laiciffonu
semitemos tub ,rehtafdnarg ,elbirret era meht fo wef yreV“
.keleB ta elims ot
,delliks yrev era yehT
,seveiht laitnetop tsniaga noitcidelam evitcetorp a morf tprecxe na :htaed eht eid mih tel ,koob
yad eht tuohguorht deirrac dah yeht smeti fo tsil eht hguorht nur dluow yeht ,thgin ta dnA
.ynoga ni kcuts ro egar htiw dam pu dniw dna
–a saw ecitnerppa s’nam siht tub ,eno sa gnikrow erofeb sraey rof ecitnerppa tsum eno yllausu dna
.ecalp ton dluoc yeht yaw emos ni tnetni
htaed naht esrow sgniht lla retfa era ereht fi
.ebur detraeh-gib txen eht rof kool dna
,edih rekciht emos otni gnilppir niks
”…tub ,revocer llahs nairarbil eht neht spahreP
worb sih no doots taewS
.lla retfa ,evom ton seod nas nymon niidiihk ehT .spahrep ,dnik ruoy rof yranoitats ooT
,sucof fo tuo tsuj tfird seye rieht tel ot yeht erew tub
.snoicipsus esiar ot hguone gnol erehwyna gniyats reven
,naht rehto gnihtyna yas ot elbanu flesmeht gnidnif
.dezeeuqs ,denethgit
,nas nymon niimiihk eht fo
,eno gnuoy ,ytilibisnopser ruoy eb ton lliw rettal ehT“
”.niaga ereht pu ytisoreneg hcus dnif llahs I spahreP
,deitpme saw sevlehs eht fo tsal eht nehw
.nodehportsuob gniredduj
.won enim era uoY
.noitrexe neddih emos ni worb sih ssorca
,lautir fo tnecs a saw erehT
,hcnul gnirud apmast ’sknom eht tae ton dluoc yeht elihW
,tekram eht ni elihw detekcopkcip rehtaf roop a
”.gnivil eht gnoma regnol on ylbaborp si eH
burcs fo hctap a fo eel eht ni dekcauovib yehT
”.yhtlaew ton si yretsanom eht taht dnatsrednu tsum uoy hguoht
straeh ’sreyolpme rieht fo ezis ehT
llah eht ot meht evom dna skoob dna sllorcs htiw kcap emarf a edal sknom regnuoy eht tel dluow yeht ,gninrom eht nI
,aet rieht ni rettub ekat dluow yeht
”!reverof rednaw lliw luos siH !luos siH“
.htroN daeh lliw I spahreP“
— ssarg eht no doolb dna thgin eht ni slwoh ,gnissim peehs a
gnillor hcamots rieht tfel dna keleB revo dehsaw tI
,keleB syawla erew yehT
yllufthguoht gniwehc
yrotcefer eht ot ylbmun delbmuts keleB
.esnopser ni denaom ylno knom ehT
.rehtaf eht sa llew sa
,yllufthguoht dewehc knom ehT
retrop a sa ylimaf a htiw ytic eht fo steerts eht deklaw dah yehT
.stam fo gnidnem tsal eht gnihsinif dna
.naorg a naht erom on eganam dluoc yehT
,kahzroO ssim ro retsim ro
.sdnah gnilbmert-llits sih ta nwod gnikool
,reeb niht tuo dellup sknom eht dna
sdnah rieht ni eno siht dleh yeht taht won ,llitS
”.syad yb robal ruo denetrohs evah uoY
.skoob wef a fo senips eht gniregnif elihw dias keleB
— erus eb ot ,ylwols — eripmE eht fo egaugnal eht daer dluoc yehT
.tegrof reven dluow yehT
,dneirf a fo ssol sih fo mih pleh ot gnihton od dluoc I elihW
,kni.oykam ta
eerf ekorb yllanif ecaf sih ni noisnet tahT
— !did yeht krow dna — dekrow keleB nehW
krow ruoy rof uoy sknaht yretsanom ehT
”,ssendnik ruoy rof uoy knaht I ,rehtafdnarG“
,roolf eht ot delppot eh
si yrots s’thginoT dna
:tfel yeht erofeb neppah dluow sgniht owt fo eno ,wohemoS
.motsuc dna wal nihtiw krow ot deraeppa syawla
.worb sih morf gnitserc snroh
,wenk yeht taht eno ton saw ,seye rieht desucof yeht nehw ,egaugnal ehT
”,edam neeb sah laed ehT“
,detaeper segap eht neewteb ecneserp eht
”.uoy nihtiw evil lliw I ,em rebmemer uoy sa gnol oS
.koob eht tuo gnidloh ,ebircs eht ot pu kcab neht
siht yawa ekat enoyna fI  .enilno
,renetsil ,flesruoy rof egduj tub ,tbuod on ,etaf mirg A .knom nwonknu na yb koob suoicerp a otni nettirw
,skoob fo senips eht gnola dapregnif rieht gninnur llitS
”?txen levart uoy lliw erehw ,keleB ,em lleT“
.krow rof seppets eht klaw I“
.aet derettub dna gnillif-gnilpmud demaets fo lwob rieht htiw deggel-ssorc nwod gnilttes ,os did yehT ”.tis
— enilef yldlrow siht yb decnartne sevlesmeht dnif dluow reyolpme eht ro
— robal rieht rof ecnattip a edam dna
.selat hguorht ylno epahs-fo-sretfihs eseht fo wonk I“
”,noitidnoc sti fo eton ekam dna llorcs eht llornu osla tsum eW .esu ot nrow oot era hcihw esoht gnicalper ,meht htaeneb sgur eht naelc dna ,kcats yb kcats
.ecno ta evael tsum uoy tub
.skoob ruo ni daer evah I ,esruc a si tI
.gniretaw seye rieht dna
.tnemhcrap fo parcs a no seton lanif emos ni gnillif no dekrow eh sa yltnesba deddon knom dlo ehT
.swap rieht ni dehctulc koob eht gniciton erofeb kaeps ot
.llewnu kool uoY“ .delbmum keleB
,keleB derepsihw rehtona saw ti spahreP
htuom sih denepo dna meht ot pu dehsad meht fo enO .gnirelloh
,teef rieht ot tpael dna slairetam rieht deppord sknom rehto ehT
F“ ”?htaed hguorht naht tegrof ot yaw retteb tahw
”,ecivres a htiw su dedivorp evah uoY“ .deremmats yeht
,gnilbmert dnah dlo
:esruoc fo dna ,yrarbiL ehT ,knoM ehT ,feihT ehT :thginot
.mih ot txen tam eht dettap eh dna elims a ni delknirc seye s’knom dlo eht dnuora niks ehT
.nioc erem dnoyeb tnemyap yna revoc dluow
.eslaf reve ,reven tub
.smaerd ni llits klaw lliw luos rieht yas ew ,eid yeht nehW
,dewohs evah uoy ssendnik eht rof niaga uoy knaht I ,rehtafdnarG“
,deliot sknom redlo eht erehw
.nrow oot erew yeht fi sraggeb eht rof tuo tes ro
.lles ot hguone ytterp ,elggums ot hguone llamS .seno ycnaf
,seirots dnif nac uoy erehw
.rennid ta omom rieht nihtiw
,reve naht erom ,won rof
”segaP eht neewteB ecneserP ehT“
,stsug ni ,sevaw ni emac tI
”.em tegrof reven lliw uoy dnA“
.daeh sih nihtiw dleh — nairarbil eht eb tsum eh desoppus yeht — knom dlo eht
.egnahcxe eerf ni ,kahzroO keleB ,uoy ot koob siht evig
,hA …yrotcefer eht ni eb lliw segaw ruoy…segaw ruoY
.gurhs lattimmocnon a gnivig erofeb lufhtuom rieht dewollaws yehT
.nruter ni don eltbus a evag dna
”?uoy htiw tae I yaM“
,gniliec eht no nettirw gnihtemos gnidaer eb ot demees tub
.boj txen eht ot yaw eht no detcelloc
.elims namuh erom eht dda ot derebmemer yeht erofeb
.syaw fo gnivrennu tsom eht ni gnitrofmoc
— meht sa snoisserpxe dna secaf emas eht evah ton od ew esuaceb kniht I
,reverof rednaw ot eunitnoc lliw dna
,niap fo yrc delgnarts a tuo tel eh dna
.ffo dehsur knom eht ,taht htiw dnA
,gnuoy erew yeht nehw
ebirt rieht fo srehto eht htiw hguone netfo devom ylimaf riehT
,detatiseh knom ehT
,yrarbil eht ot gnihsur eb ot demees yretsanom elohw ehT
.rorroh gninwad fo eno otni denrut
.noitinomerp fo neehs niht a dniheb gnivael
,relevart wollef ruoy
.namuh regnol on si eH“
.robal ruoy rof erom ecno uoy knaht I
.suoicerp erom gnihton ylneddus saw ereht
.straeh gib htiw esoht yb dereffo sboj rof hcraes dluow yeht
.ueil ni aet rieht ot dda ot keleB rof
.kaolc dna pac rieht pota tfel
,boj ot boj ,nwot ot nwot morf gnitfird dna dluoc yeht erehw krow gnidnif ot desu erew yeht os
.gniunitnoc erofeb sllabtaem wef rehtona dehsinif tac eht ,yldas gniddoN
”,hcum oot si koob siht yleruS“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,dloc ylevitcA .dloc tub
.noitapicitna htiw gnitarbiv ,ria eht ni gnuh yehT
.noislupmoc a ot nika erom gnihtemos saw ti spahrep dna
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”segaP eht neewteB ecneserP ehT“ saw sihT
.mih rof doow yrrac dna ehtal sih fo eldaert eht nur ot elba tsael ta saw I
,ebor a ni enoyna ot dewob
,yal sgnignoleb rieht fo tser eht erehw yrotimrod eht ot no deunitnoc yehT
.koob eht daer ot elba erew yeht woh wonk ton did yeht ,eroM
,rehtafdnarg ,elba ma I tahw tae lliw I“
.knom a fo htaed eht ecnuonna ot snroH
,eltsirb liat rieht tlef yehT
.kahzroO raed ym ,enutrof doog uoy gnirb yeht yam
.niks esraoc rieht tsniaga llihc neddus a gnileef ,desuap keleB
.s’keleB nihtiw ytnelp eb ot devorp serutcirts ruo fo stimil eht nihtiW
.won regae saw eciov siH .dias knom eht
,ruoh dlotnu emos dellot ,slleb ekil rehtegot gnar yehT
,detlits erew sdrow ehT
.noos niaga uoy ees llahs I spahrep dna ,tser esaelP
,sebor esraoc htaeneb gnitfihs mrof sih
,eno gnuoy ,su rof krow lufrednow hcus enod evah uoY“ “–I
tnemyap etairporppa erom a eb dluow hcihw redisnoc dna
”,rehtafdnarg ,sey…I“
,egap lanif eht fo gninrut eht tA
”segaP eht neewteB ecneserP ehT“
”.esruoc fo ,segaw ruoy ot noitidda nI
.gnineve drawot tnecsed wols ,gnol sti nageb nus eht erofeb htron daor eht no erew dna
.meht ot emac gninaem eht
,ytissecen yb boj yretsanom eht rof elam sa flesmeht decudortni dah yehT .dias keleB
.htnom a rof thgirwleehw eripmE na rof dekrow ecno I
.nam suoreneg a saw eh tub ,yats ym gnirud tnemecalper renif hcum a fo yreviled nekat dah eh dna ,esruoc fo ,nrow llew saw tI
.robal sih htiw dna yllanoitome htob ,dehsurc saw eh ,thgirwleehw sihT“
yrrow fo kool siH
?keleB ,taht raeh uoy oD“
snioc fo gab llams eht pu dekcip dna
.llafthgin yb yawa eb tsum uoY
.knom dlo eht htiw syaw a etiuq tnew
.seutats edaj llams owt dna
,emitnwod gnirud sreyolpme rieht ot yldneirf tub
.eugnot rehto emos fo saw koob eht fo revoc eht no gnitirw eht tub
.retaw htiw nwod apmast eht dehsaw neht
,keleB dekcart regnol on seye siH
.tnedurp yliranidroartxe demees evael ot ecivda eht ylneddus dna
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
retaw toh yrref dna reeb gninaorg eht werb ot gnipleh
,flesti koob eht morf emoc ot demees dah eciov ehT
.nem eht htiw pleh fo eb ot
.emoc dah yeht noitcerid eht morf eton deniatsus ,wol a
.tfig rieht saw taht koob eht daer yeht taht
.did syawla eh sa gniklat nigeb ot knom eht rof gnitiaw dna
.luferac syawla erew yehT
noitarbelec llams a saw erehT
”.luos ym evreserp
,daeh sih dewob eH
”.edam neeb sah laed ehT“
.rrup yklis a otni deppils sdrow fo repsihw ehT
smsirennam lacov dna ecarg eninimef fo tcepsa emos taht dnuof tub
,rettal eht ni pu dnuow ecitnerppa gnuoy sihT
.sepahs-fo-retfihs a erew yeht
cifironoh eht ta yltniaf delims knom ehT ”.krow lliw I dna
,sdneirf ro ylimaf on htiw tac gnuoy etilop eht
s’tnemom a retfa ,nehT
.nihc sih ot gnulc elttips dna
”.evael dna sgnignoleb ruoy dna meht ekat esaelp
,skeew owt rof doof dna roolf eht no tops a rof
nairarbil htfif-ytrof ,rayabnogtO ,I“ .ytinas dnoyeb gnirednaw ezag sih
— yhtrowtsurtnu su dnif ynam dna
.ylnmelos deddon neht
,detanimulli ,tliG
.digir erew selcsum siH
,seye rieht detreva dna nem eht ot deistruc dah yehT
.tsahga ,htuom sih derevoc knom ehT
,sgnisselb ruo htiw serugif eseht ekat ,ereh
,rehtafdnarg ,seigolopa yM“
.dessap tnemom eht neht dnA
.sllorcs dna snep rieht pu gnikcap erew sknom rehto eht erehw muirotpircs eht sdrawot llah gnol eht nwod dna yrarbil eht morf derettiks neht ,depley keleB .gnilpmurc naht rehtar
,nwot txen eht ot ffo erew yeht neht dnA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
tlef htob ,srettel esoht ,llihc tahT
stpircsunam dna ,skoob
?robal ruoy rof egnahcxe ni
.swap s’tac eht ni
.swap rieht otni kcab yllufecrof koob eht desserp dna daeh sih koohs ylkciuq knom ehT
— snioc wef a fo tnemyap llams a htiw yawa emoc dah dna
.knom eht ot yletilop dewob keleB
?thgiew hcus raeb yeht did woH
,meht ta gnirats knom dlo eht saw ereht tub
.esrever ot nageb
.ekawa elihw neve maerd ni klaw emoS“
metsys emos ot gnidrocca sevlehs rieht no kcab meht ecalp ot sknom regnuoy eht gnipleh
;daol sih rednu dehcnuh retrop eht
.rehtafdnarg ’,rednaw lliw luos sih‘ dias uoY“ ,gniyas
.ohce ylpmis naht erom won ,niaga ecno eciov eht emac ”,keleB“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.yretsanom eht ta ereh od uoy sa
,efiwdim a sa dekrow dah yehT
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.os eb ot devirts ti hguoht sa
?yas ot tahw wonk yeht did woH ”.yleerf tpecca I“