,namuh gib a saw eH
.esolc os tlef lla ti tuB
!hcuoT“ ,detuohs tnavresbO
:dnim s’tar tpeni yllaicos eht ni retsiger ot stnemom artxe wef a koot tI
.tas slaiciffo eht fo lla erehw htoob nedoow elbmuh eht ot
.gniht emas eht uoy ksa ot gniog saw I ,yllautcA“
.mih ot gnitteg saw ti
eye eht ni mih dekool yboT
,derumrum diurd ehT
sdnoces fo elpuoc a retfa ylnO
:rekinom sih denrae eh erehw saw tahT
.seye sih morf dnas eht gniraelc dna hcti na gnihctarcs
.dleihs dna drows sih rof dehcaer eh sa mlac ylegnarts tlef nidalap ehT
.gnihtemos deen uoY
,esrevinu sonaP eht ni ecalp sekat yrots sihT
,retnec daed demia saw tsurht eht ,emit sihT
.stserof nrehtuos eht fo sevle dliw eht gnoma ’retnuh ytnuob‘ a saw ehS
.lledneW dehcaorppa ehs sa ria eht hguorht detfird ekoms teews ehT
.sresuort sih pu decal eh sa ecaep renni fo erusaem emos rof gnikool
.relkcub dna edalb sih teem ot swolb fo riap tsrif eht rof gnicarb
detrats lla ti tuB
”.ta tseb er’uoy tahw od dnA .meht tegroF“
”.ecaps fo setsaw lekoy derbni ,deniarb gnud
.gnir eht fo tuo gnilbmut erutaerc llams eht dnes dluow tnenoppo sih morf kcolb suolucarim dnoces a nevE
.llor sih detelpmoc lledneW
.yrolg dna nioc rof stropsdoolb lagel-isauq ni gnitapicitrap
.noitcarf a tsuj ,denepo seye s’lledneW
”?ti si eno hcihW“ ,derumrum eH
kcab denrut ylevislupmi tub
.resol on eb dluow ereht
.dworc eht hguorht tpews
.yob nibac a fo fiaw reh m’I dna ,drol etarip a s’ehS .ees uoy ,lasrever elor emos od ot sekil efiw yM
.kcolb dleihs gnisiurb a htiw tem saw pitliaT
tnedirt sih ro edalb sih rehtie ecaf ot tnaw dluow rotitepmoc elgnis a ton tub
.siht od dluow eH“
.llew sa ytic tnecajda eht fo flah ylekil tub
,meht debircsed tseb taht evitcejda eht saw eman s’itey yrevE
,yrotciv ni saw eh sa taefed ni trops a fo doog sa ,erdnA
”.rewsna ym dnuof I kniht I“ ,dias lledneW
gniws sih fo mutnemom eht dellortnoc eH
.top elttil rieht otni aet emos depmud namuh gib ehT   ”.haeY“
.hA“ .elims gib a otni ekorb yrroJ
,tpmetta tsrif sih morf gnihton denrael d’eh fi sa saw tI
,llor dna evid ot tarerew eht decrof
.sgel yzzuf sih dexelf eh
.gnihton htiw eno saw eh ,emit siht tuB
,decnuonna ylmlac tnavresbO
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,idraciR lliB yb
.hsalc stsileud decnavda tsom s’redrO eht fo owt dehctaw
”?erac uoy od yhW“ ,deksa eH
.gnir eht fo retnec eht sdrawot peerc suoituac
.mihw sseltser a no selim fo sderdnuh dellevart evah t’ndluow eH
”.hsivreD ,setunim owT“
,emit tsal ekil tsuJ .tpael lledneW
,thgif a ni sdnah tsetsaf eht evah t’ndid uoy fi neve taht tnaem llub gib ehT
,sredluohs sih dellor eH
si yrots s’yadot dna
”?elbuort fo dnik emos ereht sI .yrroJ“
;yrotsih s’lledneW wenk ohw elpoep wef eht fo eno saw eH
.wolb gnimocni eht sdrawot nups eH
,ffo degrahc eh nehT
erew htoB .eof eliga ,tsaf sih morf kcatta tuo lla na detciderp namdrazil eht yltnerappA
”.seniH lledneW riS susrev redirtS erdnA“
.yrotciv eveihca ot sdnuob fo tuo tnenoppo ruoy worht dna pu kcip yllanoitnetni t’ndluoc uoy hguoht
.htoob s’egduj eht sdrawot wob ot ecarg doog eht dah eh
”.ris ,uoy knahT .yrt ll’I“ ,saw ylper tsenrae siH
susrev laguoDcaM renbA riS
,tnenoppo nellaf sih ot dewob lledneW
.hgiht s’tnenoppo sih fo selacs eht tsniaga dehsurb ylerab drows nedoow sih fo pit ehT
,neveR yrroJ riS saw retnec eht nI
.noisulli sih gnivaew dehsinif drab itey eht litnu tsael ta
.sdnah htob ni daeherof reh dehctulc dna sdrows nedoow reh deppord ehS
,serats suoicipsus eht rehtaew ot evah t’ndluow eH
.retfa noos wollof ot gnioob detcepxe nidalap ehT
.sebij rieht tuoba derac eh taht wonk meht tel ot tnaw t’ndid eH
,nebiD detinU fo sodanoicifa thgif dezilivic eht fo tsoM
.tnet sih fo tuo deppils namuh eht sa
”edalB tsetsaF ehT“
,elzzum sih fo edis eht gnola swap sih fo skcab eht debbur eH
.ria eht tilps hgual tsubor a ,daetsnI
.noisiv sih fo segde eht dnuora ni tperc ssenkcalb A
?noitautis siht eldnah eh dluohs woH
,gnir epor eht edisni secalp rieht koot yehT   .evilA .deticxE
”?seniH riS ,tsafkaerb rof tnaw uoy od tahW .tsafkaerb roF
.tuob a now eh emit yreve
.lacisyhp eht dednecsnart niap emoS
lleW“ ,dias nam ehtil ehT
.sdaptoof erab fo rovaf ni stoob tabmoc dennuhs tarerew eht
.seirrap tfed dna sehsals gnidnilb htiw dellif saw etunim txen ehT
.erats suoibud a saw tI
,noititepmoc s’raey siht rof ytic tsoh eht
”.gniht siht niw og ,em taeb ev’uoy taht won
.ereht t’nsaw ylpmis tarerew ehT
.ylniatrecnu dehsal liat s’lledneW   ”.yrrow uoy t’nod
,dworc ybraen eht ylno ton gnihcaer ylisae eciov gnimoob sih
---   ”.now ydaerla ev’I ,yaw rehtiE
,erusserp evisserppo fo dnik siht fo setunim wef a retfA
.hcaer emas eht tuoba htiw sdrowsgnol gnidleiw erew meht fo htob tsael tA
ruf kcen yarg trohs sih hguorht swalc debmoc nidalap ynit ehT
redluohs eht no tar eht dettap diurd ehT
’.seye ruoy sa tsaf sa ylno er’uoY‘ :lledneW dlot ecno yboT
.lliw reehs dna swalc ni-gud htiw
,srotitepmoc sih fo tsom ekilnU
.dedeen erew sehcrot dna
.elims flah a mih evag neveR riS
.rettihc elttil ecreif a dehsaelnu dna
,hguoht thgie pot eht ni tfel sleeh fo elpuoc a tsael ta evah ll’eW
.elihw eht lla htnebkeN-leD ot reyarp a gnitnahc
.thgilf koot tar eht sa wols ot demees emiT
idraciR lliB yb
.sedalb ecitcarp nedoow htiw thguof saw tuob hcaE
ecnerefretni ro sdrazah yna rof kcehc dnoces tsal a
.edalb sih fo pit eht htiw gnidael
srotcarted sih ta sesruc gnirehtiw fo seires a gnihsaelnU
...ytinav fo tca na spahreP
.tsetnoc eht fo yad lanif eht no srepmac fo ytirojam eht pu edam snaf draheid dna srotitepmoc-xE
.yks eht otni pu lledneW deluah dna nwod dehcaer
,lautum a ni gnigagne
.ffo mih tuc tar ehT   ”-dna rof reehc nac dworc eht elpoep neewteb ecnalab doog a tnaw uoy ,lleW“
.nossel rehtona dedeen dna
.trohs napsdnah a tsael ta eb dluow tsurht sih taht raelc saw tI
,yenruot eht ta devirra eh ecnis emit tsrif eht roF
.snaf esoht fo riap a deretnuocne
…elttab fo dleif eht otno deklaw ehS
,troffe eht mih gnirapS
.draeb regnig citsejam ,gnol a gnitrops tub tooc a sa dlab
,llitS .stnemtsujda lacitcat rieht
”!seniH lledneW riS susrev simaraS
,kcab sih no talf morF
.tarerew eht ot tuo efink elttil a dleh neveR riS ,ylsseldroW
,idraciR lliB yb
.sleeh revo daeh gnilbmut tar eht tnes dna
.nwod decnalg lledneW
snopaew ecitcarp eht no stnemtnahcnE
;ecnatsid eht desolc stnatabmoc eht yllautnevE
.did elpoep lamron tahw si sihT
.gnorw ylbartsnomed
.droceR fo draB eht sa saw elor s’tnavresbO
.eno siht ,ysae eb annog toN“ ,dias nam reggib ehT
.semit lla ta nosrep ym no neddih sevink evif dnuora evah I
.ylkciuq thgif eht hsinif ot saw tnetni s’nam ehT
,deeps siht ta tuB
,drawrof detoocs namdrazil eht
.niw llits dluoc uoy
tarerew eht dna namuh eht
.emit nevig yna ta aera gnithgif eht fo noitrop tnacifingis a gnissapmocne
.enilced dluohs eh ,etilop gnieb tsuj saw nam rehto eht fI
.ylper lattimmoc-non s’nidalap eht ta delwocs neveR riS
.epacsdnal talf eht dettod serif tsafkaerb elttiL
.deraor ecneidua ehT
,kcalb ni lla sserd ot deneppah ehS
.htoob gnigduj eht morf yrnopaew nedoow rieht pu dekcip neht dna
”.taR riS ,sknahT“ ,dias dal reggib ehT
.ffo daeh sih koot ylraen liat s’namdrazil eht fo pans a ,eciwT
.erutnevda txen rieht sdrawot noinapmoc sih dewollof neht dna ,depip eh ”!sknahT“
,deriter yllaiciffo saw eH
.ria eht hguorht tuc ti sa rulb a tsuj ratimics ecitcarp sih
---   ”.yrt llew nmad d’eh kniht I“
euqrot sih detserra lledneW tuB
.setuor kcatta s’nidalap eht fo flah
,oreh lacol a morf tnemesrodne tnerappa eht dna egnahc edutitla neddus sih yb desufnoC   ”!hazzuH“
.stnemom lacitirc weiver ot deriuqer saw noisulli
tnaem taht yltcaxe tahw rednop ot tfel saw lledneW
seitud sih morf ecnesba fo evael a nekat evah t’ndluow eH
.lacimoc tsomla saw ekahsdnah derutan doog ehT
rehto eht kcin ylerab tsuj ot gnitpmetta saw meht fo hcaE
”.renniw eht si seniH lledneW riS .hcuoT“
,dworc gnireehc eht otni tuo dekool
”.ti fo wohs a ekam ,niw ot deneppah I fi oS“
,rehto hcae tsap devom stnatabmoc owt eht sA
.ydaer saw eh ,emit sihT
,hcum oot denrael eh erofeb ffo nam rehto eht tuc ot dnim fo ecneserp eht dah lledneW   ”-dna ,snoolatnap klis lufemahs ni pu sserd em sekam ehS
,tarerew eht dnuora dna revo kcits egdums eht dessap allebanaS
.seniH riS ,snialliv lufwa ekam snidalaP
...derit ,deniard tlef eh
,dias ehs dna ria eht hguorht tuc mlap reh nehT
,daeh taerg sih gnikahs saw eH
.enobtsaerb s’nidalap eht ta thgir
---   .slanifretrauq eht ot ti edam d’eH
.dnah gnitiaw sih otni kcab thgir gnidnuober
.ni devac daeh sih gnivah saw eh naht
,tuo denword yletelpmoc eb dluoc eh erofeB
”.tsael tA .nezod a flaH“
.palf tnet eht hguorht nees eb dluoc draeb citsejam dna ecaf sih ylno litnu kcab dils yrroJ
.oga gnol dniheb tfel eh taht sonaP ot noitcennoc A
.koot eh pets hcae htiw decnuob riah nworb ylruc ,trohs siH
,aera eht tpews seye neerg reH
elttab fo dleif eht otno tuo deklaw eh fi esrow teg ylniatrec dluow ti
.seye eht neewteb thgir tneduts sih deppat dna
,yalper yranoisulli eht ta pu dekrims tsuj retnuh ytnuob ehT
.dnoces a fo noitcarf a koot egnahcxe eritne ehT
.ylwols os reve ,deddon tarerew ehT
.ecaf sih fo tnorf ni tsurht erew sdrows erutainim owT
,ecaf sih revo retaw emos gnihsalps saw eh sA
.elcric epor eht fo elddim eht ni gniteem
.gnir eht fo saera nepo erom otni gnillor ro gnitnirps
.ylsuorogiv dnah sih koohs redirtS .rM
”.desserd teg ot deen I ,setunim wef a eb ll’I“ ,dias eH
.mih elttes dluow klat-pep elttil a ebyam …llitS
.eof llams sih ta tsurht laturb
,ssarg eht otni swalc sih gud eh nehT
.tsurht a tiab ot gniyrt
.mih ot resolc teg ot deen uoy dnA
.deripsni tlef eh gnihtyna fI
.esiurb gib eno ekil tlef kcab siH
,tuob eht decnuonna neveR riS
,strohs fo riap a ylno erow eH
.mih devol sdik eht dna ,strap eseht dnuora dnegel a fo tahwemos saw yrroJ
edalb tsetsaf ehT
”.emit hguor a uoy gnivig saw dworc eht taht sdal eht fo elpuoc a ot noitnem did I tuB
,dehsalc stsileud ehT
,sdrows ecitcarp elttil gnivaw sdal gnuoy elbigirrocni wef a yb del ,tnahc A
.srotcarted sih erongi ylpmis ot lortnoc fles eht dekcal eh tuB
.eciov s’ynomereC fo retsaM eht ni tcepser tub gnihton saw erehT .yrroJ saw tI
.nosaes eht ni retal gniod eb dluow yeht tahw dna
,erif rieht ot pu derepmacs snihcru elttil owT
”.tsal ruoy eb t’noW“ ,detciderp eH
.dworc yldneirfnu na fo dnuos eht tuo tuhs ot kcab srae sih nip ot gnivah tuohtiw tnet sih ot kcab deklaw lledneW
.ria eht ni drows elttil sih gnivaw
.tnedifnoc saw enot s’tnavresbO ,emit sihT
.tsrif lledneW degguh dna
.erom ecno ni degrahc eH
.delbmut tarerew ehT
.paeh a ni gnidnal
.elcric epor eht fo driht retuo eht edisni tsuj gnicnad
.rorrim eht ni nam eht dah ylno eh tuB
nwod mih deklaw relliK elbraM ehT
.egar renni sih niatnoc ot stpmetta tnelubrut erew snoitatidem sih fo tsoM
?eugirtnI ?elbuorT
.thgilnus thgirb eht otni tuo deddolp lledneW
,hteet sih tirg eH
.tarerew eht ekaw ot koot ti lla saw eltsur tniaf A
”…ruof rebmun laecnoc ot od ot evah I tahw eveileb t’ndluow uoY
.egaugnal ydob rieht hguorht sevom s’tnenoppo ruoy etapicitna dluoc uoY
relkcub sih dnuof kcik peet a nehw yradnuob epor eht revo deddiks tsomla eH
s’lledneW   ---   .edih ot gniyrt yletarepsed os saw eh taht sraet yppah eht yb saw eh sa dednilb
,dias eno rellat ylthgils ehT
.deltsur spalf tnet eht
.riahc reh fo tuo saw allebanaS ydaL yletaidemmI   .wolb ’lataf‘
.rotciv eht ot kcab deddon ehs dna
,erif ybraen eht morf rebme na debbarg ehS
,tnemom a rof desuap eH
.niatrecnu saw eciov s’tnavresbO
”.seniH lledneW riS
.egde eht ot resolc teg ot si
.tsetsaf saw meht fo hcihw llet t’ndluoc eh
.lrans elttil a htiw llordeb sih otno rorrim eht dessot eH
.tsurht edis dnilb yletelpmoc a ni tuo dna
,noitseuq ni elur eht detouq neveR riS
.ehtil saw ydob siH
.regna ni dedleiw erew yeht fi
.dennuts saw dworc ehT
.regna sih retsam ot denrael d’eh ylno fi
.smraerof dna sdnah gnidulcxe dna
.naorg a htiw seenk reh ot llef htekriZ ydaL
”!hazzuH“ ,detuohs eh ,daeh sih evoba tarerew eht gnidloH
no deppets seot sih gnivah tuoba deirrow ssel raf saw eH
.hgiht tfel s’fle eht ot hsals kciuq gninthgil a
,kcab mra sih dekcoc dna drows sih nups eH
.yradnegel saw dleif gnileud eht fo dne raf eht morf dehcaorppa taht namdrazil ehT
.detrats gnioob eht
.sesnefed s’tnenoppo rellams reh ni sgninepo rof gniborp
ytic nezorf ,etomer eht ni secnamrofrep sih derebmemer snaretev eht fo emos tuB
.kcab eht no mih dettap dna detrons llub gib ehT
ffo tuc yllaitnesse dleihs rewot siH
.sdnuop dnasuoht a dehgiew ti ekil tlef mra dleihs siH
mih esirprus did tahW
,ecalp koot selttab erehw gniraelc eht dehcaorppa lledneW sA
.lledneW neve toN
,deliob neve saw retaw aet gninrom rieht erofeB
.edrag ne tfed a htiw snaf wen sih detulas eh sa
,elttab riaf fo dog ’sonaP ,tesmeR-orA ot noitacided s’nidalap eht dnA
.ydaer eht ta sdrows ecitcarp
sa nwonk saw simaraS
,evom evisneffo tsrif sih edam eH
.gnitnahcne saw elims siH
edalb s’redirtS .rM sa kcarc prahs a saw erehT
,stneve fo nrut siht yb dennuts ylthgilS
”luof“ fo seirc dna feilebsid eht htiw pu tup ot evah t’ndluow eH
,nidalap eht htiw elcric ot detrats dna kcab deppoh ehS .ylerab tsuj tub
.ylksirb daeh sih koohs nam dlab ehT
.dleif tsaE eht ni tuo saw lledneW ,retal setuniM
,noitacifilauqsid etaidemmi tnaem strap ydob timil-ffo htiw gnikcolb yllanoitnetnI
,tar a fo rats gnisir eht taeb eh fi oS
.sduolc yarg yrgna fo tes a dniheb raeppasid ot denetaerht nus noonretfa eht ,ffo decaf riap eht sA
drows sih worht nidalap eht was dworc eritne eht
,tnet sih ot kcab ti ekam t’ndid ylraen eH
.enrobria saw eh nehT
.nam rellams eht tpurretni ot nrut s’namuh eht saw tI
.sehcni artxe eht niag ot
.dneirf wen sih ta delims eH
.dworc gnireehc eht sdrawot denrut eh nehT
.noitareneg a ylraen rof duola nekops neeb t’ndah taht rekinom a saw tI .hsivreD ehT
”edalB tsetsaF ehT“ saw sihT
,redluohs s’renbA riS revo drowsgnol sih deggard eH
.saw tar eht ohw aedi on dah
”.lagel yltcefrep si toof s’eno htiw dnuorg eht ot edalb a fo talf eht nip ot gnitpmettA“
.kcab efink sih koot yrroJ
.haey ,lleW“ ,dias eH
.wols tub gnihtyna saw renbA riS dnA
.pu tnew reehc evissam a
.sreliops ronim niatnoc yam tI
.detaerter eh sa delkcuhc namuh ehT
,htaerb sih thguac lledneW ecnO
.relkcub sih esiar dna tlah a ot diks saw od dluoc eh llA
.esae gnikcohs htiw esneffo s’tnenoppo sih delleper simaraS
,elttab fo dleif eht ssorca egrahc ot tnenoppo sih detcepxe flah lledneW
,seot sih no thgil deyats lledneW
,ecaf elgnis a yfitnedi t’ndluoc eH
.htiw tcennoc ot redirtS .rM rof gnihton saw ereht tuB
,raeh dluow enoyreve taht os ylduol ,decnuonna ehS
.sretceps yb detnuah erew smaerd siH
,erutsop s’htekriZ ydaL eht ni egnahc thgils a gniypS
yrc yrotciv eht saw tI
”.tsafkaerb erahs ot ekil thgim uoy thguoht tsuj I .on ,oN“
flesruoy ecnatsid dluoc uoY
,detnahcne ton si lledneW riS“
”.retsaM ,wonk t’nod I“
.gnimoc tsurht eht was eh nehw htaerb sih ni dekcus eH   .wols ooT
.dednuow eht ot dnet ot ton tub
.sreehc gninefaed eht elffum ot kcab deihs srae
,anera gnithgif eht denifed taht epor-rohcna kciht eht revo deppoh lledneW sA
,dessucsid saw ecneuqesnoc fo gnihtoN
.palf tnet eht sdrawot detniop drowsgnol laer yrev a
.mutnemom sih gnitserra
.denoitnem saw lledneW nehw soob tneuqesbus eht tuo denword ylraen
,mih retfa nur ot detrats eno rellams ehT
.eltsihw tniaf a draeh eh nehw pu decnalg eH
.lledneW ,ereh pu s’tI“
.seniH riS ,oreh a syawla t’nsaw I esuaceB“
.hctiwt ot rae tfel sih desuac gniltsur A
.stnatabmoc eht esylana ot deirt lledneW
.niaga flah dna thgieh sih ylisae
”.mmm-mmmM“   ”?eid dna revo llor annog tsuj rey oS“ ,dekrab eH
,derumrum lledneW
.teef sih ot kcab
.ria eht hguorht decils dnah s’allebanaS   .gnitnuh ytnuob
.ecnatsid eht desolc ylbissop evah dluoc tarerew eht erofeb noitisop draug otni kcab dellup dna
.metsys sih fo tuo sevren eht ekahs ot deirt lledneW
.edalb eht fo talf eht pu detnirps nidalap llams eht
dna ygolirT diputS rehtonA fo rohtua
,evissam saw hcaer s’tnenoppo siH
.sgel sih denruhc dna
,egatnavda hcaer thgils a reh evag smra yldnips s’fle ehT
”.erdnA fo dnik ytterp saw taht ,yeH“ ,dias eciov A
,edit eht sa elbativeni sa ,tuB
.dnuorg eht sa ylkciuq sa ni dehsur ytilaeR   ”.dnim eht ni si
.sekirts esicerp s’tarerew eht tsniaga dnefed ot deganam ylerab eh sa toof kcab eht no namuh
sgnilwarcs dekni htiw decafed neeb dah taht tnet a ni flesmih yb lla gnittis eb t’ndluow eH
”.neveR riS ,uoy knahT“
.hgual ytraeh a tuo tel ruatonim ehT   ”?weiver seluR
.dnah reh desiar allebanaS
.daeh denroh sih koohs dna
.deifirolg si tesmeR-orA erehw si elttab tub...“
.gnitaehc fo snoitasucca derettum eht
.nihc sih gninrut regnif tnaig a tlef eh nehT
.sdrows ecitcarp llams eht fo stlih eht otni kram sih devrac ylluferac lledneW
”.renniw eht si seniH lledneW riS .hcuoT“
.secalp rieht koot srethgif eht sa gnir eht denimaxe allebanaS
.relliK elbraM ehT
.mraerof sih fo trap dna tsirw s’lledneW derevoc dnah yzzuf ,evissam s’renbA riS
,hctip eht otni gud swalC
.elbatpecca saw toof s’eno htiw dnuorg eht ot edalb a fo talf eht nip ot gnitpmetta hguoht
.thgie poT :mih tih ti nehT
.eof llams sih morf skcatta fo evitpeced tsom eht rednu neve
.gnihcaorppa tnenoppo sih ees ot dleif neerg eht ssorca dekool eH
.eof rellams sih degrahc namuh ehT   ”.nigeB“
.llat saw eh sa gnol sa ylraen drowsgnol a dna
.gnilims saw eh tuB
.ecaf sih fo tnorf eht no thgir etiuq tif ti ekil leef t’ndid waj sih dnA
,swap raer nwo sih no kcab saw eh ecnO
”?hcnew gnivres a sa thgilnoom uoy oD“ ,deksa eH
,pu dleh rewop ysae dna pihsnamsdrows tfed
ekans deyojrevo na ekil dehtirw liat siH
,derepsihw dna revo denael yboT
”…htiw gninnip …gninniP“
.nissassa na ylirassecen t’nsaw ehS
.detadimitni t’nsaw eh tuB
,roirraw dednetxerevo eht sdrawot gnarps eh nehT
.tsurht dna ria eht otni pu thgiarts tpael lledneW ,ylnedduS
,edis rehto sih nO
.nwod eid ot esion eht rof detiaw dna
,tneiciffe na hcnual ot gnignul
.seot sih neewteb mraw saw ssarg hsul ehT
”?gniht elohw eht niw d’eh kniht uoy oD“ ,deksa eH
.desirprus t’nsaw lledneW
.’troseR tsaL fo ssecnirP A‘ dna
,semit thgir eht ta rewop war ylppa ro
,saw hturt eht tuB
eman s’oreh rieht gniraeh nopu snaf eht fo raor ehT
.hcaer evitceffe reh fo timil eht ta thgir gniyats
,stneve eseht ta kciuq os saw noitca eht semitemoS
.relkcub s’lledneW tsniaga detnemgarf
.ecnalabretnuoc a sa mih dniheb ria eht hguorht gnirettulf liat
.deggurhs nam dlab ehT
.degilbo renbA riS
.ekip a yb delapmi yletelpmoc neeb d’eh fi sa demaercs namdrazil eht tey dnA
.noisufnoc ni derumrum dworc ehT
.demranu m’I ,hsivreD em llik t’noD“ ,dias eH
luof denrut rehtaew eht esac ni dekots tpek
,rehtaew eht tuoba deklat riap ehT
.nihc sih rednu yltneg desserp drowsgnol nedoow a fo pit eht ,retal tnatsni nA
pu mra sih delgna tarerew eht
”.meht rof ti od d’eh dnA .siht yltcaxE
.flesmih tarerew eht naht rellat saw dleihs rewot s’tnenoppo sih taht tcaf eht no sucof ot ton deirt eh ,snopaew rieht tcelloc ot tnew yeht nehW
”!sniw seniH lledneW riS“ ,decnuonna tnavresbO
.esuoH ecI ni kcab
.langis s’diurd eht gnitiawa
”.mmmh mmmM“   ”.navarac yawanur a ekil stih eh tub ,dal naem a ton s’eH
;gnol ylbidercni saw drows dednah owt s’tnenoppo sih taht tcaf eht erongi t’ndluoc eH
.lledneW dnuora nwod wols ot demees emit ,waj eht ot ekirts tceridni eht morf dezaD
,reffo eniuneg a saw ti fi tuB
.gniviecer saw eh spals redluohs fo rebmun eht morf etirovaf nwotemoh a ylraelc
.ratimics devruc dna
.rotnem ruatonim remrof sih fo spetsfooh eht ni gniwollof saw eh fi noitautis siht ni eb t’ndluow eh
”-c uoy od yhW .em ,naem I .oN“
.itey derruf etihw evissam a
.ecnetnes sih dehsinif tnavresbO erofeb gnir eht fo tuo yaw flah saw simaraS
.ria eht hguorht decils dnah reh
.skcolb mraerof sih fo eno otni rewop dna ecap fo noitcejni neddus a tup nam rellams eht
.elcric ot detrats dna teef sih fo pirg eht dexaler tarerew eht
.elbmag ot emit saw tI   .deppart
.tnemom yna ta pop thgim yeht ekil demees ti deticxe os
,delbmur ruatonim ehT
.ti fo enon gnivah saw ruatonim ehT
yaw rehtie gniws dluoc taht emag a saw tI
”?mmmH“ .gum sih otni aet eht fo sgerd eht deruop yrroJ
relkcub llams sih pu koot tar ehT
.dehctiwt sreksihw siH
.enif tsuj htob meht detius hcihw
.moc.idracirllib.www//:sptth
.rorrim dlehdnah elttil a otni derats eh sa
.tesmeR-orA fo nidalap a rof etairporppa t’nsaw gnipytoerets fo dnik tahT
.ruoted a edam sdal eht nehw saw
.terger fo gnap a tlef yletaidemmi eH
,nwoT retaT morf roirraw derruf nworb gnirewot a
,nips-dim noisave eht detrats eH
tneduts dna retsaM
”.smeti detnahcne yna ssessop eh seod ron
esahcrup dnif toof llams sih tlef eH
.enif tsuj nissassa nevle eht tius dluow ssenkrad taht desoppus lledneW
del evah dluoc eh taht efil A
,raf suht neeb dah noitapicitrap sih ot noitcaer cilbup sa dab sA
,daeh sih ni artnam drow ruof eht detaeper lledneW
.elcric eht fo tuo gniddiks diova ot gniganam ylerab
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,deifilauqsid erew uoy dna gnir eht denifed taht elcric epor eht evaeL
.yldneirf gnieb saw eH .pihsdneirF
.ecnelis ni gnir eht fo tuo deklaw eH
.namsdrows ecreif a gnieb ot noitidda ni rotca egats dehsilpmocca na saw eH
---   .reehc suotoir a otni kaerb ecneidua eht raeh eh did tnet sih ot kcab yaw flah saw eh nehw ylnO
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tarerew a reven saw yboT ,niaga nehT
.evitcnitsni saw snaf nwotemoh eht morf esnopser ehT
.mih ta kcab derats rorrim eht ni tarerew ehT
.tnet elttil eht fo foor eht pu edam taht cirbaf eht gnihcuot
,aet kcalb derahs yehT
.wolb suoicoref eht yb thguac teg ti tsel shgiht sih fo eno dniheb liat sih gnikcut
,retsim ereht esaelP“
,egnahcxe yreve retfa dnA
.tnih a mih evig dluow flesmih naht esiw erom raf enoemos taht dehsiw eH
.evol sih sserpxe ot denrael eh ylno fi
?tsafkaerb ot mih gnitivni seinomereC fo retsaM eht saw yhW
.rehte eht ni detaolf dnim
.gnihgual detrats allebanaS
.thgir neeb dah nidalap eht ,tcepser eno nI
.ecaf railimaf a saw
.stnapicitrap eht regnadne thgim taht
.tros emos fo kcits labreh na til ehS
.snopaew retrohs gnissessop etipsed
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.ria eht otni detfil gnieb flesmih tlef lledneW ,niaga ecnO
”.wonk I nidalap tsrow eht er’uoY“
’?od yboT dluow tahW‘ ,flesym ksa I
”?neveR riS ,tnaw ay d’tahW“ ,delbmum eH
.feiler htiw dehgis ehs ,stnemom wef a retfA
.reganeet a saw eh ecnis mih deugalp dah taht regna tneserp-reve eht yawa hsup ot deirt eH
.’aelf‘ dna ’tegdim‘ fo
.revuenam ot moor rof gnivrats flesmih dnuof lledneW
,yrrap ot deganam ehS
.melborp a eb ot gniog saw sihT
.nidalaP riS ,yrroS“
”?sedis ruoy ot tuo smra ruoy dnetxe uoy dluoC
:detneserper yeht tahw wenk eh tub
,troffe eht morf gnikahs llits ,lledneW
.esruoc fo tluser eht toN“ ,dias eH
.os did lledneW ,deifitsyM
”.sniw seniH lledneW riS .hcuoT“
.noipmahc ylekilnu tsom a fo
.dlrow taht hcuot dluoc eh ebyam ,tuo dehcaer tsuj eh fI
.dleif tnemanruot eht no evisuba taht gnieb diova ot flesmih gnidnimer ylkciuq
,gnir eht evael ot denrut eh nehT
.selbuort reh rof reyarp gnilaeh ronim a deviecer ehs sa yllufeur daeh reh gnikahs
”?uoy t’ndid ,ti ot pu mih tup uoY“
.lla ta erehwon morf ti ecudorp ot demees eH
,lluks s’tnenoppo sih fo ffo decnuob edalb ecitcarp ehT
.noititepmoC stsileuD lanoitaN eht fo dnuor driht eht otni ti edam evah t’ndluow eh
.dworc eht revo llef hsuh A
:ecnadnetta ni sredle dna stluda eht yb deifilpma saw ti nooS
.sgge deliob dna ,daerb liart
,tfola drowsgnol nedoow sih dleh eH
.dnobagav a ekil gnikool
.erom ecno ssalg evitcelfer fo erauqs elttil eht otni derats eH
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.redluohs tfel sih evoba ecnaraeppa feirb a edam liat ekilpihw siH
.noitadimitni fo mrof a sa yalpsid no ydob detplucs llew sih fo tser eht gnivael
.dehsalc htekriZ madaM dna lledneW fo noisrev degralne na ,dleifelttab eht evoba teef neT   ”.evresbo esaelP
dleihs etik muidem a rof detpo namuh ehT
,ruatonim evissam ehT
,llordeb sih ni ylkciuq pu tas eH
”.gniog erif eht tog ev’I .dooG
…thgis lausunu erom raf a ,tfel eht no dnA
,oga flah a dna edaced A .esuoH ecI fo
.selacs sih decarg taht laet thgil dna neerg peed fo dnelb lufituaeb eht fo esuaceb tsuj toN
,reh denioj dworc eht ni elpoep lareveS
.reidlos a sa eergidep sih fo esuaceb tsuj ton dnA
,stops thgit fo tuo teg ot ygrene dnepxe ot dah eH
,draeb nosmirc sih dekorts nam ehT
,lios eht otni swalc dnih sih gud lledneW
”!hsivreD !hsivreD“
ylkciuq teef sih derevocer eH
,noisnetxe lluf otni derrulb mra siH
.stneve eseht ta raluger a saw ehS
”?nidalap elttil ,dnuorg eht ot edalb ym nip ot ekat dluow ti kniht uoy od uoy fo ynam woH“
.traeh s’yboT ni tsrif emac syawla wonS eht fo redrO ehT
,seye rieht ,deeps dnah rieht dehctaw eH
eht fo emit eht ta rehtona eno fo egnar gnikirts ni erew stnatabmoc owt eht ekil deraeppa t’ndah tI
.gnir eht fo erom ffo gnittuc
,ni ti nier dluoc eh erofeb wam sih fo tuo saw noitasucca ehT
,dnim s’tnenoppo sih ni deretsiger yllaer ti erofeB
diurd nevle flah deriah nevar eht
hcaorppa s’lledneW dehctaw seye deroloc tsur-nosmirc siH .tnavresbO
.sonaP nrehtron revo lla devoleb saw
.relaeh dna reciffo ytefas s’tnemanruot eht sa devres ohw
dellac saw eno siht taht wonk ot trofmoc a fo tahwemos saw ti os
.dworc eht hguorht dessap rethgual fo elppir A
,tnatsni elbissop tsal eht ta nups eH
ezah krad taht fo edisni tuB
.elzzum sih fo napsdnah a nihtiw emac pit tnulb s’eromyalc nedoow ehT   !hsoohW   ”!nigeB“
.detrats esualppa eht sa neve
”.seY“   …yas dluohs eh
.rewsna eht wenk ydaerla eh fi sa
.tnatropmi denmad gnihtemos rof saw ti sselnu
,eil a s’tahT .lleW
,noititepmoc a hcus retne ot ffo emit eht nekat evah reven dluow yboT ecniS   .dereviaw reven
.mih derusserp dna
,decnuonna elbmur mlac s’itey A
dray ecitcarp s’wonS eht fo redrO ehT fo hcrop eht no gnittis erew yeht ,ylnedduS   .yboT
.hcum oot peew dluow ydobon
’?od yboT dluow tahW‘
.dworc eht revo llef ecneliS
’espylacopA diputS rehtonA‘ neewteb ni
,yltfos delrans eH
.www//:sptth no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY .agaS yhI ehT
.edalb sih gniworht gnitalpmetnoc fi sa
,ytisoiruc dna ytniatrecnu s’dworc eht deleuf tsuj sihT
.noitingocer ni drows sih evaw yldetraehflah ot dnim fo ecneserp eht niag eh did
.ecarg laicos dna srennam ni snossel tnecer erom sih fo emos dellacer eH
.ria eht hguorht tuc epiws liat driht a ,daetsnI
.gnidael dleihs evissam
sdnah koohs stnatabmoc ehT
.tegrof reven ll’I ecneirepxe na si sihT“
.ylhsilwo deknilb lledneW
.tneve eht fo noitacilper a evah I“ ,decnuonna eH
.mih ot saw kcab s’namuh eht taht dnoces a fo noitcarf eht nihtiw
...“   .trats taerg a toN
,palf tnet eht hguorht dekop daeh s’namuh A
.spil kcalb niht revo etihw gniwohs sgnaf
”?uoy t’nod ,niw ot tnaw uoY
,eenk eht evoba derocs saw tih tsrif eht litnu deunitnoc tI
,drawrof deppets-kciuq stnatabmoc htoB   ”!nigeB“
.ecnalab ffo eof ruoy gnikconk
”?ruof ro eerhT“ ,desseug eH
”.weiver rof noisulli na nommus tsum I ,seigolopA ?hcuoT“
,derettups lledneW sselhtaerb a
,niap eht derongi simaraS
.ylf eht no nalp sih deifidom tarerew ehT
.thgil elbissop tseb eht ni redrO sih tneserp ot gniyrt tsuj saw eh taht flesmih decnivnoc eh tub
.tnemniatretne rof tsuj s’taht tuB .sey ,lleW“ ,dias nam gib ehT
.troppus rof tsirw s’renbA riS otno dleh
,ezilauqe ot tuoba erew yeht ekil dekool sgniht nehw tsuJ
:slaniF eht gnitsetnoC“
.latnoziroh dleh saw eromyalc s’ruatonim eht
…gninnuhs eht ,dworc elitsoh ehT
.eergidep eurt sih
.yad eht fo hctam lanif-imes tsrif ruoy roF“
,allebanaS saw thgir eht nO
,kcab s’llub eht revo ylsselecarg delbmut neht
.drow rehtona tuohtiw deraeppasid namuh ehT
.derocs saw tih lagel a taht tnemom eht wonk erutaerc eht tel dluow
.edalb a fo pit eht htiw
,yruf reh nwod deniar ehS
dnah eerf sih htiw revo dehcaer eH
.sedalb dekram ylwen rieht ffo gniwohs dna setispmac ybraen dnuora gninnur llits erew ohw ,sdik eht sdrawot walc a detniop lledneW
sredluohs sih derauqs eh daetsnI
.elcric eht fo edis rehto eht no fle gninaorg eht dnetta ot gnivom erofeb
.esneffo erofeb noitavresbO .seye eht htiw
,cinorom eseht tegrof oS
.devom ydoboN   ”.nigeB“
,elbmuts ynit a dengief eH
.erusolcne elttil eht otni deppets neveR riS
mih ot resolc teg ot yaw ylno ehT
.nihc sih otni dleihs elttil sih fo egde eht demmals ekirts eht fo ecrof reehs ehT
.tsael eht yas ot ,ytirar a saw ecaep renni fo dnik sihT
”.keew siht tol a taht gniksa neeb ev’I
.raw notgnirraH eht gnirud stroffe sih rof smodgnik elpitlum ni dethgink neeb d’ohw reetavirp a
,thgir sih ot ffo gnikool yb flesmih detcartsid eH
.gniws sih fo mutnemom eht llik dluoc tnenoppo sih erofeb egnar otni egrahc ot deirt dna
.yaweel fo htdaerbsriah a sa hcum os nevig fi
”.ruatonim ehT“ ,dias neveR riS
!pu dekrow teg ot evah uoy neht lleW“
.lios eht gnippirg swalc dnih sih morf deniag eh taht noitcart artxe eht dekil eH
level kcen ta epiws latnoziroh A
”?edalb tsetsaf eht s’erehW“
noititepmoC stsileuD lanoitaN a gnillacer emit drah a dah snamuh fo tsedlo eht nevE
”edalB tsetsaF ehT“yojne esaelP
”.htekriZ madaM susrev seniH lledneW riS“
stroffe nairatinamuh sih ot eud detnarg saw doohthgink siH
,dehsinif eh sa ecalp ni detarbiv syob ehT
,gniod m’I slleh eht ni tahw wonk t’nod I nehW“
,seye s’dworc eht nI
.ssenhguot dna ecnelis yenots sih rof osla tuB
”.tsom naht nialliv eht gniyalp fo sniap eht tuoba erom wonk I yas erad I
,’sucric der‘ eht ni rats eganeet a saw eh
…reh fo enecs eht ta ecnedive suoivbo on evael ot sa os kciuq eht ot daeh reh evahs dna ,sdrows trohs nedoow fo riap a dleiw
,enileert nretsae eht revo esir ot detrats nus eht sA
.duht delffum a htiw teknalb remmus niht sih otno llaf ot ti gniwolla ,drows sih deppord eH .denaorg lledneW
tarerew eht pleh ot nwod dehcaer dnah derruf nworb evissam A
,ssima saw gnihton taht deifsitaS
.yrrap nipskcab a detucexe eh sa desrever mutnemom siH
dah evah dluoc eh taht ylimaf A
.nwod dna pu deppoh dal rellams ehT   ”?kram rey ekam ay’dluow
”?snaf tsriF“ ,delkcuhc eH
.seitic lareves fo snoitalupop sselemoh eht gnoma
.flesmih niartser ot deganam tub
.sdnah gnirac ,detnelat reh yb desselb t’nsaw taht
.sdneirf yna mih niw t’ndluow ylniatrec
,ria eht ni sdnah sih werht etarip-xe ehT
”?esaelp oot em neht dna ,retsim sey ,seY“
.ytisoiruc eniuneg htiw
”.tuo teG“   ”…ecnahc yb ,snoolatnap klis yna evah t’nod uoY“
.dnuor txen eht rof tuo srotitepmoc eht gnillac ,dednuos nroh ehT
”?rewsna eht s’tahw dnA .eya ,hO“