don s’rentrap gnirraps a evag riM
.trof siht dliub t’ndid
.ti depsarg ylmrif dna kcommah desivorpmi eht ffo tpael eh
.xon tenam anu senmO“ .siht
.daerht nedlog htiw enobralloc thgir rieht htaeneb derediorbme saw—
rahavaraf llams A
.trof eht fo retnec eht ni elbat citsalp a morf seikooc pihc-etalocohc fo gab a debbarg aynA ”?sevlesmeht rof maerc eci suoiciled taht lla ekat meht tel annog er’uoY .nom’C“	 ”.gnihtyna
,ecnedifnoc elbakahsnu na reh htiw deirrac riM
uoY“	 .degnoleb yeht erehw thgir saw aynA
.ereht tuo er’yehT“
?aedi doog a si siht erus uoy erA“
”.eihsulp a tsuj naht erom semoceb elletS nehT
etihw wons ecaf rieht
.walc rieht detcarter aynA sa deddon riM ”.renekawa na tub
.elzzum sih fo edis eht fo tuo gnippird loord ,deddon
.tnemom a rof dnuora dennacs taes s’revird eht ni xof citcra ehT
,htaerb reh rednu esruc a derettum dna seye reh dellor neR
.ydob eht htiw tcatnoc ekam ot dah stih deificeps—
tis ot ecalp a tuo flesreh gnivrac ylkciuq
.stnemevom ym etapicitna ot deen uoY
.llef ehs sa reh thguac aynA dna
,tcnitsni erup no gninnur saw aynA litnu pu gnideeps stnemevom rieht
.eadnus suoicsul eht tub
”.evitaitini eht ekat dluohs ew kniht I“
.nuJ ot txen reh gnittes erofeb
.teprac eht htiw tcatnoc edam yeht sa mutnemom rieht esrepsid ot dellor aynA
.tnemom yna ta ecnuop ot ydaer dekool yeht taht
attoG“	  .riM ta kwahamot eht gnuws neht dna
llitS“	 ”.wonk uoy ,ereh tuo ti tiaw tsuj dluoc eW
.renroc tsaehtron eht kcehc
.tluav yot s’ecalap eht ni yawa dekcut selfir trad maof tsuj naht erom erew ereht
,evom tsrif eht edam riM
”?tey gnitae dehsinif uoy evaH“
,revo delbuod aynA
.stnemevom rieht fo dnuos eht pu revoc ot
,edis ot edis morf lerrab terrut eht tpews riM
”.eno elttil ,doog did
.thgif s’aynA saw siht gnizingocer
ruf depporc-esolc riehT
,ycamolpid lacitcarp ekil sesruoc ciretose erom htiw gnola
.redro gnikcep eht ni noitisop sih fo tnedifnoc erom raf dna
!ronoh tuoba s’tI“
,delbmurg hcamots s’aynA ”.maerc eci eht htiw ereh kcab steg amaM litnu tsael ta ro
.tnecrep derdnuh-eno em htiw er’uoy fi ti od annog ylno m’I tuB
er’eW“ .meht dnuora mra evitcetorp a depparw iaK ”.dnatsrednu
.nwod meht hgiew t’ndluow ti os llaw eht tsniaga pu elfir rieht gninael ,dehgis aynA ”.drapoel wons etirovaf ym htiw gnikcik-ttub fo tops a rof pu m’I sseug
,hgiht reh debbur ylfeirb ehs sa decniw riM
,dewollaws d’yeht sa noos sA
.pets ruoy hctaw ot nrael ot deen uoY“
,rehtona eno no dekcol erew seye riehT
.soniM gniK fo yhtrow htnirybal a rof edam pu delip yldrazahpah neeb dah swollip eht yaw ehT
.deppetsedis riM
,trela saw drapoel wons ehT
.elcihev eht fo deb eht ni flesreh gniretnec
.evocla detcetorp a ot drawrof detnirps iaK
etagivan ot gnitpmetta xof citcra ro
.uoy ni ecnedifnoc etinifni evah I
.adnap der eht tsniaga esolc pu deltsen dna thgiled fo laeuqs tfos a tuo tel
.sttub rieht kcik nac ew kniht I“
,esolc nuJ dleh aynA
”.won tuo kcab ot etal oot
sehcnup thgit dna skcik gnipeews s’aynA degdod riM
.ratceN dna aisorbmA .R.S.P eht morf langis ssertsid a detpecretni dah resiurc ym dna ,oga sraey emos saw sihT !thgir s’tahT“
.yteixna htiw gnitarbiv
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
”!tressed retfa emit yrots syawla s’ti ,terref
.daeh sih koohs iaK
.egeis degnolorp a dnatshtiw dluoc trof wollip rieht erusne ot ni delggums dah iaK skcans eht ta redluohs rieht revo decnalg yeht dna
.dlo sraey net ta sterref tluda tsom naht reggib meht gnikam
.sgnaf rieht gnirab
,seotatop leep gnipleh saw I elihW
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb
.sllew leehw eht dnuora romra muinatit gnitnilg htiw
.sevlesmeht tcetorp ton dluoc ohw esoht tcetorp ot htgnerts eht meht gnivig
,ot pu er’yeht revetahW .onnuD“
,htaerb peed a koot aynA ”.dnatsrednu
.hteet rieht dettirg aynA
,eihsulp drapoel wons sih evag iaK
.pirgerof rebif-nobrac eht dnuora wap rieht gnitsujda
.ottom s’eripmE latrommI eht fo noitnem eht ta delkcuhc iaK ”.thgiR“
.tsehc s’drapoel wons eht dnuora depparw saw taht tleb citsalp yarg a morf noitinumma trad sti werd tI
,detrevid saw noitnetta reh sa noos sa degrahc yehT
,gnirewop saw ti tahw erus yllatot t’nerew yeht elihW
,swodahs peed tsac
,latrommI nrob-larutan a saw hateehc ehT
elbisneherpmocni gnihtemos htiw deilper aynA
.elzzum rieht otni noitanimoba yraniluc dellif-ragus eht delevohs yeht sa
.reidlos-repus a eb ot pu gniworg fo aedi eht ot desu gnitteg llits erew yeht
,nrettap ttim naor kcalb a dah
.deb s’gnogieL eht ni stals eganiard desiar eht fo eno no thguac toof s’riM sa dnah reppu eht dezies aynA
elttil a detnurg iaK
.revoc otni teg
.strad maof fo egarrab a htiw aynA gnitsalb
.tbuod fo hsiugna eht tlef reven gnivah
seye erihppas larutannu dah drapoel wons ehT
.gnihtyna ro su gnivrats era stnerap ruo ekil ton s’tI
.ecnats reh demuser riM
,sbuc rieht esiar ot ruof fo spuorg pihsnik demrof slatrommI
reweS cirtcelE ehT
— ”pirt yna rof tuo eye na peek ,yaw eht yB“
oS“	 ”.gnihtemos ot pu yletinifed er’yehT
,sllaw wollip eht fo eno nwod deggut neR
.edis thgir sih no rosicni tnorf deppihc a dna
.dednetxe ylluf rehto eht
.erifdliw gnizalb a fo rewop war eht htiw kcurts aynA elihw
.tcadid larutan a saw riM
.snoihsuc fo elip a fo pot no
.tuhs pot eht demmals dna
.etag edis eht ot daeh rieht dekcilf yeht
.reh no kcams gnicnalg a sa hcum os dnal t’ndluoc aynA dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD
ezeerb lufyalp a ekil dewolf riM
?noitulos citamolpid a ot emoc lla nac ew ebyaM“
.sehctam gnirraps ym nees ev’uoy wonk I
,nageb ssecorp noitatnemgua eht erofeb syad eht rebmemer llits dluoc yehT
.emitdeb erofeb laeh dluow seirujni yna erusne dluow sniev rieht hguorht gnisruoc setinan eht hguoht
ylliS“	 ”?emit yrots rof emit ti sI“
.lwob eht fo pil eht revo gnillips fo egrev eht no saw ti litnu eadnus s’aynA gnippot ,maerc deppihw fo snac detsif-elbuod igasU
toof fo ssenteelf eht htiw gnivom
.meht gnihtaehs-er erofeb ecrof fo wohs a ni swalc deppit-muinatit reh dehsalf ehS
,gnihtyna rof ydaer eb ot dah reidlos-repus latrommI nA
I“	 ”.krow maerd eht sekam krowmaeT
erA“	 ”.nwod draug ruo tel t’nac eW
,ezis rof elitnecrep hteitfif eht ni saw aynA
.tsif desolc a pu dleh eh sa dekrep rae thgir s’iaK
.WAS eht desiar eh sa elzzum sih fo nirg tnedifnoc a dah eH
,stiurf citoxe yb deppot erew maerc eci allinav fo snollag lareveS
itnoC fo tnuocsiV eht sa noitisop s’iaK
.reh tnioppasid ton dluow aynA
.yawa dellup eh sa kniw suoveihcsim a aynA tohs iaK
,rihsmah rieht saw tI
nemodba reh gnitcetorp wap eno
”.ereht teg ew nehw ereht teg
”?tnemevom yna pu gnikcip uoy
.noitartnecnoc htiw desrup spil reh
”raW maerC ecI ehT“ saw sihT
”.llew gnissergorp si euqinhcet ruoY
tsuJ“	 ”?noos sruoy nrae uoy t’noD“
.ytiniffAruF no krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
gninniw-drawA oeL eht gnidulcni seigolohtna suoremun ni
”.su gnoma ecalp ruoy evresed uoy evorp ot emit s’tI
.relddot a erew yeht nehw setarip yb dellik stnerap rieht
.sbuc rieht rof emas eht gniod erew srehto ehT
,iaK tsniaga esolc pu sevlesmeht desserp yehT .thgis tod der
,oga sraey emos detpoda neeb dah yeht hguohT
.rehtegot detsiwt steehsdeb nezod a flah morf edam
drawrof terrut eht nips ot riM rof detiaw eH
tiftuo ralimis a erow iaK
.ecnavda ot langis eht gnivig erofeb
,delggirw tik terref ehtil ehT
”.ecnanidro yvaeh eht tuo kcarc ot deen
?poocs artxe na steg ohw
,dil eht detfil igasU
,dias aynA ”,nopaew eht etiuq
.edagirB thgiL eht fo yruf war dna
.yldipar gnisaercni saw hctip eht tub
.redluohs rieht no wap gnorts a gnicalp
.sesiri suonimul reh gnihctam
,derevocer aynA .eye reh ni maelg a
.mlap reh fo leeh eht htiw keehc rieht dekcams neht dna
.tsiaw rieht dnuora ylevitcetorp depparw liat reh sa
.sgnippot rehto eht revo ecuas etalocohc deldal ehs sa
.noitisop elbatrofmoc erom a ot kcab gninael
?tahW“	 ”.eciton yeht erofeb ecnatsid eht esolc nac ew kniht I“
,delrans aynA  ”.ti esu ot emit s’tI
.esruoc eht rof rap saw emityalp gnirud sesiurb wef a gniniatbO
.ycagel ym gniyrrac fo boj enif a
riM wohs ot emit saw tI
.snmuloc troppus nedoow owt neewteb dednepsus tliuq a morf meht ta nwod dekeep iaK
iaK	 ”?gninrom siht uoy dlot rehtaf ruoy tahw taht saw ,iaK“
dehsilbup neeb sah krow s’xuaF
.lerrab s’terrut eht fo egde gnidael eht no daeh sih gnikcahw gnidiova ylworran
si yrots s’yadoT dna
hateehc eht fo ecart on dettops yehT
,nopaew rieht deppord aynA
,yllaniF	  .wollof ot elbissopmi ylraen emaceb noitca eht
.ecitcarp otni egdelwonk taht tup ot sgnilbis rieht tsap ti tup t’ndluow aynA
.edisni kcats elohw eht thguorb yltneg dna
,evitaitini eht koot
I“	 ”?ti tuoba klat annaW“
wap s’aynA edisa dehsurb riM
.emit ekat tsuj ll’ti kniht I“
.redluohs rieht no wap gnirussaer a decalp neR
”raW maerC ecI ehT“   yojne esaelP
,yllanosrep meht detceles dah amaM
?ydaerla ,eitros
.kcab sih revo gnuls saw dad sih morf nwod dednah
”.gnipmac egaruocsid ot ngised eht ni ytilibarenluv fo dnik emos eb dluoc erehT
,tuo walc xedni rieht gnikcilF
,tcatnoc edam toof rieht sA
.taht tegrof reve t’nod ,won ylimaf a
”.siht ekil t’nod I
.evom rof evom riM gnihctam
.htgnerts aynA evag taht tbuod taht saw tI
.meht delcric ehs sa
s’tahT“	 ”.yob dab siht fo daol a teG“
,elat reh nips ot nageb ehs sa
.ffuns ot pu erew yeht erus t’nsaw aynA dna
.eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
.tsiaw rieht dnuora tleb eht morf kwahamot dalc-maof a deveirter yeht sa revoc emos meht edivorp ot
.pirg eht no gnimmurd ylsuovren swalc rieht
.egrahc ot deraperp aynA
.flesmih deretnec eh sa htaerb peed a gnikat
,god.ecioveht ta
hctaW“	 .stnemom fo tsefeirb eht rof taefed fo thgiew eht tlef yeht sa seye rieht desolc aynA ”!snaeB“	  ”.seriw“ — leets sselniats fo htgnel niht a ssorca deggut toof gnidael rieht sa nwod dekool aynA
ylkciuq os degnahcxe swolb
”,deleep seye ruoy
ruf diletsum kciht rieht ,nosaes retniw eht rof desserd saw aynA
strad maof artxe deirrac tsiaw rieht dnuora depparw tleb egalfuomac latigid ehT
.dednecsA eht fo eno er’uoY
,ebut citsalp a otni dekcud yehT
.meht ot thgif eht ekat rehtar d’I“
”?poocs eno dewolla gnieb ylno tuoba gnihtyna dias ohW“	 ”?adaR ,thgiR“
.rihsmah elttil ,no emoC“
.deilper iaK ”,ruoh na
.sdrow reh yb detevir moor eht ni luos yreve
,teef rieht ot kcab gnignirps erofeb ffo sevlesmeht tsud ot tnemom a koot yeht sa
erA“	 ”.gnivom peek s’teL“
epor a drawot gniws ot nageb iaK
.eikooc pu-dehsum a htiw tuo deffup skeehc
rO“	 ”.daeha pu hsubma na eb dluoc erehT“
.htgnerts ro thgieh ni iaK hctam reven dluow yeht taht wenk aynA ,gniworg llits htob erew yeht elihW
.daeh reh fo kcab eht debbur yldrawkwa neR
,esop evisnefed a otni werd ehs sa
syad eseht fo enO
,mutnemom emos pu tliub d’eh retfA
etagliat eht pu delbmarcs aynA
,thgin lla ereh tiaw ot tnetnoc m’I tub ,uoy tuoba onnud I“
,oS“	 ”.adaR ,noitseggus tnellecxe na saw tI“
”?ereht si ,ecalp siht dnuora tnemom llud a reven
,kcik gninnips a htiw reh dessim aynA retfA
”.tnorF nretseW eht no teiuq lla s’ti ,won roF .smees ti
liat dezisrevo siH
.seenk dna swap rieht otno nwod deppord aynA
,iaK evititepmoc-ylecreif
,drawtuo tohs rehto eht elihw
,gnidaer thguat ymedacA ehT ”.spart yboob
.wets ikaniahc s’rehtom htrib rieht fo slwob gib dna enihsnus mraw ffo evivrus ot demees yeht nehw
,xof citcra dna ,drapoel wons
s’teL“	 ”.reverof su morf edih t’nac yehT“
.ehcolc revlis evissam a gnitroppus trac ecivres moor a fo tnorf ni smra reh dessorc neR
.redluohs sih ot nopaew citamotua dauqs noitaroproC stnemesumA ujnaW eht thguorb eh sa
tcapmoc a pu gnippilf erofeb epocs eht dehcated dna spilc gniniater eht deppop aynA ”.aedi dooG“	 ”.egnar esolc ta gnigagne eb thgim eW
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.maerc eci fo lluf dloh ograc eritne na laets ot dediced dna htoot teews a nettog dah setarip emoS
,rewop denifer htiw devom
.erofeb tnemom a gnidnats neeb dah aynA erehw ssorca gniylf sbro etihw fo daol a tnes stellep maof htiw dedaol eromyalc a sa yaw eht fo tuo meht devohs iaK ”!tuo
.sreilednahc daehrevo eht morf thgil eht fo tsom tuo gnikcolb
.ezingocer t’ndid aynA sthgiled ciretose erom dna ,ydnac ymmug
,dlog nups fo roloc eht ,ruf siH .nuJ
meht fo edis rehtie no snoihsuc ehT
.egrahc ekat ot ssengnilliw s’iaK detcepser aynA ”.ti tog uoY“	 ”.derevoc
aynA	 .saw ehs sa latrommI na hcum sa tsuj erew yeht taht
.ruf neklis sih gnikorts ylwols
,trid morf emac aynA .raW ralletsretnI dnoceS eht fo sedis htob del gnivah enil citeneg reh
.redluohs rieht degdun iaK
I“	 ”?rihsmah elttil ,won ti leef uoy oD“
esnopser thgilf-ro-thgif eht fo noitapissid wols A
.kcab sraey wef a enim lennosrep-itna na htiw toof s’rotcurtsni na ffo nwolb dah taht
,yroeht lacitilop
.gnitneirosid erew sllaw s’yawegassap eht fo serutxet dna snrettap fo tnemtrossa ehT
”.rihsmah elttil ,yllautcnitsni emoc dluohs ekirts lliw I erehw fo egdelwonk ehT
I“	 ”?naem I tahw wonk uoY
.eraps ot moor htiw edisni elzzum rieht tif ot hguone egral noops gnivres a gnisu lwob s’aynA dellif igasU	 ”?eh si ,won thgir maerc eci eht gnivres ton s’eh ,llew ,haeY“
.moor eht otni deddap
ekilnU	 ”.gnissergorp era snossel esoht woh ees s’teL
”?ti eldnah nac uoy erus uoy erA“
.mih ecnalab ot drawtuo gnurps
.sevlesmeht gniretnec
.elzzum rieht otni seikooc gnimmarc nageb dna trapa egakcap eht erot aynA
rufdaeh s’terref eht dekorts ylrednet dna nwod denael neR
.edis eht ni reh dewoble ,igasU
.seye rieht dnuora ksam nworb etalocohc eht rof tpecxe
aynA	 ”.amaM htiw ereh revo tiS .nom’C“
”.did ew esruoc
”?ksir elttil a tuohtiw efil si
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.gnihton rof gninnur shtnom eerht rof htnoM eht fo tedaC niw t’ndid I“
.taorht s’riM tsniaga ti desserp aynA
”.ehcac snopaew eht rof gniog eb dluoc yehT
”?erus uoy erA
,hateehc a ,stnerap rehto rieht sa dehctaw aynA
,derumrum iaK ”,ytsorf yatS“
,epocs rieht no sucof eht htiw delddif aynA
.mih dniheb teg ot terref eht degdun yltneg iaK
.semit ta gnitneirosid saw meht no detsiof ynitsed suoirolg a gnivaH
.erafraw allireug dna
,wollip eht tsniaga esolc pu dehcoocs yeht sa dias aynA
lartsehcro dna thgil gnihtemos dnuof eh litnu skcart eht hguorht dellorcs drapoel wons ehT
adar fo noitisop eht nevig latrommI eno htiw
gnihton rof seye dah eH
drawpu dekool aynA
peeK“	  eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
.dooG“	  .meht fo tuo dniw eht dekconk taht tug s’aynA ot baj woble na dereviled riM
,noohpyt a ni sehcnarb s’eert a ekil devaew dna debbob ehS
.niarret eht gninnacs seye evitisiuqni sih
.neht yb IA ym evah
.strof wollip owt eht neewteb dnal s’nam on eht ni efil fo sngis yna tops t’ndid aynA
,ecin dellems eh tsael tA
tuB“	 .lobmys gnay-niy a fo roloc eht ruf htiw tibbar arognA na saw ehS
,skrep niatrec dah mooryalp eht fo renwo eht gnieB
.elbaitasni saw etiteppa rieht ekil demees ti woN
redlo elttil a saw iaK
dah riM .aynA gnicaf mlap
.snihc rieht rednu teknalb a gnikcut dna
,dnuora nups ehs sa mutnemom laitnatsbus gnitareneG
”raW maerC ecI ehT“
.aynA ,no emoC .riaf t’nsi
,swollamhsram ,selknirps
”.elfir repins 99-epyT CAK a pirts dleif ot woh gninrael erew uoy
.reggirt eht no regnif
sknahT“	 ”.dleif eht ni tuo er’ew elihw ynapmoc nuJ peek lliw elletS
I“	 ”.ytied fo tros emos er’ew kniht ynaM
,srodirroc gnitsiwt eht etagivan ot tnecs s’drapoel wons eht desu yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
sa peek eht fo raer eht raen tsehc yot nedoow etanro na nepo deppilf iaK
.seye rieht dellor aynA ”.rihsmah gib ,os yas uoy
.pal reh dettap ylgnitivni ehS
pu til seye s’neR
.rehtie slatrommI eht fo trap m’I ekil leef t’nod I tub
,syoT noisicerP niginöK morf ledom tsetal ehT
,pu terrut eht fo lerrab eht nups
rufdaeh s’aynA delsuot eH
sdradnats latrommI yB
tsirw sih no rekcart noitom a ta gnicnalg
.dnatsrednu t’nod yeht tahw raef elpoeP
.meht pots ot hguone t’nsaw tI
.repeels detoof elprup peed a yb detnemgua
.slipup rieht dnuora deniamer llits taht lezah llud eht fo tuo gnisir dlareme hcir a
gabnaeb ybraen a no seihsulp owt eht gnittes erofeb
,sesiri rieht fo roloc eht tfihs ot gninnigeb saw ssecorp noitatnemgua ehT
.tut-tut elttil a meht evag eH
”?meht kcajih ot ydaer uoy
ecalp ni swollip eht gnidloh tonk eht didnu aynA
.gniniart sevil eritne ruoy tneps evah lla uoY
repeels detoof reH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
efiL“	 ”.thgif riaf a yldrah s’tI
,serneg ynam ssorca gnitirW
,yawa deleehwtrac riM
.regnif a fo pans eht ni meht neewteb ecnatsid eht gnisolc
.metsys oidua eht lortnoc ot ytiliba eht gnieb meht fo eno
riM	  .tsaf gnisolc dna
,tenalp erehwon a no nrob
.ecnarussaer demit-llew fo tib a detaicerppa syawla terref eht ,esiarp htiw ygnits yllausu t’nsaw neR elihW .dehsulb
.srehto eht ot adar
.nwod hateehc eht derats yeht sa ecnats rieht koot yehT
.elzzum rieht otni tekcap eht fo redniamer eht detlit yeht sa
,rehcaet a ton ma I“	 .ylivaeh gnitnap
.owt ro noihsuc gnidurtorp a tsniaga pu deltsoj yllanoisacco yeht hguoht
”.uoy fo daeha yaw
s’erehT“	 ”.rihsmah gib ,noitcurtsni ruoy rof uoy knahT“
,xof citcra eht dehsiuqnav gnivaH
,keehc eht no kcep a meht gniviG
redeef eht otni tleb eht dils eh sa dekniw iaK
.rorepme na rof tif drobsagroms a gnilaever
.stegdag fo yteirav a edisgnola
.evissecxe…tib ynit a smees maerc eci revo raw A
.tnuom leets-sselniats eht tsniaga yldeticxe depmuht liat siH
.su tuoba klat klof nommoc eht yaw eht draeh ev’I
,detteuorip ehs sa delbmuts hateehc ehT
.gnikaerc sbir dna gnibborht keehc
aynA	  ”.tey uoy fo latrommI na ekam ll’eW
od ll’uoY .aynA ,euqinhcet dooG“
.delkcuhc aynA ”.deb eht tew ylraluger seitied kniht t’nod
ekil tnuts yzarc a llup ot tuoba erew yeht eveileb t’ndluoc yehT
hcaer ysae nihtiw wollip tsegral eht debbarg terref ehT .emas eht did iaK
,yawa ecnatsid emos llits saw esion ehT
.taht naht retteb od nac uoy wonk I tuB“
,teprac eht tsniaga tuo doots
,pih rieht tsniaga wol tsif eno
,sbuc lamron gnoma ni tif t’nod I“
itna delerrab-irt eht deef ot edis eht ffo delgnad
.derevoc si xis ruo erus ekam uoY .tniop ekat ll’I“
guh feirb a ,airamletS
”.thgir er’uoy kniht I“	 ”.emit
.tnuoc t’ndid wollip a gnikcahw ylpmiS
,hateehc ehtil a ,rennug eht sa spil sih ot regnif a dleh iaK
.em naht retsaf dna regnorts er’uoY“
”?won thgir gniod eb thgim yeht kniht uoy od tahW“
.thgiR“	 ”?thgir ,lla su stiawa thgin enO
”?tuB“	 .snoitatnemgua latrommI eht ot sedisnwod eht fo eno saw
”.klat pep eht rof
.yrotagrup driew siht ni kcuts m’I
.yawa sretem ytnewt morf tegrat a fo eyesllub eht no trad maof a tup dluoc ti
enihw dehctip-hgih eht saw tI
.seye sih dellor iaK
deliated ylgnivol os erew seihsulp htoB
s’tI“	 ”?meht ekat nac ew erus uoy erA“
.trof rehto eht ot resolc on erew yeht
ll’eW“	 ”?gniog er’uoy erehw wonk uoy oD“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
s’teL“	 ”.doog ton s’tahT .taht ,hO“
I“	 ”.dnuorg hgih eht evah ew nehw sevlesruo esopxe ot deen on s’erehT“
.derekcins ehs sa pu gnikrep srae gnol s’igasU
.rotom cirtcele na fo
.ria tneibma eht morf denaelg evah thgim yeht gnihtyna pu gnirevoc
”!noos meht dnif ll’eW“	 .riM
.gnivom teg s’tel ,woN
flaH“	 ”?neeb ti sah gnol woH“ .srieht ot
aynA	 .uf-gnuk fo elyts gnahzaugaB eht derovaf syawla
citemhtira dna ,gnitirw
,tsehc sih tsniaga thgit WAS eht tpek iaK
tleb noitinumma eguh A
,siht fo setunim wef a retfA
.sdnoces wef yreve
.srae rieht neewteb dednuop traeh rieht sa etagliat eht tsniaga gninael
,tnorf eht ni xof citcra eht htiw deltserw iaK sA
fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.retal tnemom a esion eht thguac aynA
.ecalp eno ni derehtag saw kcaP rieht nehw noisacco laiceps dna erar a saw tI
,uf gnuk niloahS nrehtroN morf nward ecnats evissergga na ot deppord aynA
hgih teef xis dekcats neeb dah steknalb htiw rehtegot dehsal swollip fo snezoD
.ydaer leef t’nod
.hgiht reh ot kcik mrif a dereviled yeht sa riM drawot gnihcnup
,elfir rieht desiar aynA ”?pu s’tahW .oN“	  ”.thgir
esruoc fo ,dnaherofeb nopu deerga lla—selur ehT
tuo sretem wef a ylno saw dayd eht ,dnuora deleehw dah riM emit eht yB
,tnemom a rof rehto hcae ta yltnetni derats owt ehT
.enotirab wol a ni repsihw ot rae s’aynA ot txen thgir ni denael drapoel wons ehT
,dnas tresed fo roloc eht saw
.egde pot eht evoba morf tuo gnikeep elfir rieht fo epocs eht
ll’eW“	 .mra rieht fo koorc eht otni mih deltsen ylkciuq dna pu mih dehctans aynA dna
”?yllaeR“	 ”.maerc eci revo thguof neeb s’taht raw tsrif eht t’nsi siht ,wonk uoY“
”.nuf dah uoy taht si srettam yllaer tahw
.doowradec dna otnemip ycips ekil rodo ytraeh a
fO“	  ”?thgir ,aedi trof wollip eht htiw nuf evah did uoY“
,dleihsdniw eht morf yllooc dehctaw iaK
”…degnoleb ti erehw kcab maerc eci taht teg ot boj ym saw tI
.meht dexaler senomorehp larutan s’neR sa gniwols taebtraeh rieht desnes aynA
.aynA ,latrommI enif a ekam ll’uoY“
”!aynA ,maerc eci eht tuoba ton s’tI“	 ”.evissecxe…tib
m’I“	 ”?yaw ruo no sehcac ecnanidro eht fo eno barg dna yrt ew dluohS“ .kcalb ni
eripmE latrommI eht fo lobmys eht—
trof ’sgnilbis rieht morf htap gnidniw eht
,gnimlehwrevo tsomla emaceb esion eht sA
.ecnedifnoc fo level lamron reh ot kcab ydaerla ,deddon riM
.elbapac ssel on hguoht
”.ylkciuq detalacse sah sihT
.elcihev no-edir flehs-eht-ffo na naht gnicanem erom raf saw ti
ll’I“	 ”.uoy rof ti od ot dnuora em evah t’now uoy
,deb eht otno dna elcihev eht fo egac llor eht revo tpael iaK ”?thgir ,I dna aynA
.sucof rieht deneprahs enilanerda fo egrus A
.poocs elgnis a htiw tnetnoc m’I yllanosrep ,wonk uoY“
.thgir ton s’gnihtemoS ?taht raeh uoy oD“
.sllaw elbartenepmi mrof ot
fI“	  ”!prahs kcolc’o thgie ta deb ot gniog ton dnA !yrolG
.sgniraeb rieht peek ot teprac yarg llud eht no desucof aynA
.trof wollip eht fo peek eht hcaer ot drawnwod ecnatsid trohs a gnilwarc
elfir ettehcelf maof deidob-ynagoham A
.tnemecalpme terrut a no dnuora deleviws
”!taht naht retsaf eb
.neR ta tuo eugnot reh dekop riM
A“	 ”?ew llahs ,eitros a no og s’teL
nirg gnisaet a mih evag igasU
,sredluohs sih dexelf eH
.dekcots-llew saw mooryalp sih tnaem
.em nwohs tsuj ev’uoy naht uoy ni thgif erom evah uoY“
.tuo thgis ruoy pawS“
.reh dniheb liat yffulf ,gnol reh gnikcilf ,delkcuhc neR
dna rehtom evitpoda s’aynA saw adnap der ehT
tahW“	 ”.yksir…smees tahT“
,IA lanosrep s’neR
.kcen rieht dekcirc dna riahc dellif-daeb a ni nwod deppolf yehT
,sbuc latrommI rof yot tliub-motsuc A
,iaK naht rellams ylthgils saw ehS .nug tfarcria-
,pilfkcab lufecarg a demrofrep riM
.gnol oot rof llits neeb s’tI“
,eihsulp netram enip rieht dettops yeht erofeb tnemom a rof dnuora dekool aynA
ilatrommI ilged ozzalaP eht ni snoihsuc eht fo tsoM
.dah reve d’yeht stressed tseb eht fo eno saw tI
.mooryalp eht fo elddim eht ni niarret suodrazah mrof ot pu delip ylitsah neeb dah
kool ekil-regdab ,gnicanem a dah tI
”.su rof doog ton s’ti
nevelE ypartaS morf seeniart fo hctab dab a fo draeh dah yehT
.tabmoc wap-ot-wap ni delttes eb dluow siht taht egassem eht gnitteg
ehT	 ”.terref elttil ,ydaer teG“
strad knip toh htiw dedaol
,slirtson s’aynA ni yvaeh tas tnecs siH
,deb eht ffo deppoh yehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.gniralf slirtson rieht
.evlewt nrut I litnu skeew erom wef a
.meht hguorht dehsarc elcihev lacitcat thgil gnogieL inahuoR-iakgneD dezis-flah a sa revo delppot meht fo tnorf ni snoihsuc
”?he ,ytrid swap ruoy gnitteg fo diarfa
.seitud gnikaterac detaicossa sti dna
drapoel wons eht ta tuo eugnot rieht dekop aynA ”.neht