;emilc elbatipsoh ssel
,ssap ot dewolla dna yhtrow demeed eb ot eh saW
.tuops s’nisab eht evoba flehs eht morf lewot llams a koot dna desaet azzE
.muirbiliuqe ot resolc werg oitar elam ot elamef eht sa gnidaf erew
.dednetrop yad txen eht sraef tahw ton dna
.sih evoba neeb syawla dah
.zoR ,ereh t’nerew uoy fi deracs erom neve eb dluow I“
eciov sih ni ssenrettib eht draeh zoR
.yranidro eht fo tuo gnihton
.raen saw zoR nehw derreferp ehs tub
.tecuaf eht desolc dna
.tecuaf eht ediseb talf a morf elttob ssalg llams a dekculp dna
.etatiseh ton dluow ehs
llaw tnecajda na no rood rehtonA
.liat s’azzE fo esab eht evoba tser ot emac sdnah s’zoR
,azzE tsuJ .zoR ,azzE“
teef sih fo sdap ytsud eht yb emit a ta eno
kcab tcejorp eht tuoba sgnivigsim reilrae sih lla gnirb ot yas ot tahw yltcaxe nwonk dah tub
,sredluohs reh decarg lwahs redneval ,reehs A
,htgnel dna ssenkciht tnereffid a hcae
.reh ta kool ot gnilliwnu zoR ees ot flesreh htiw desaelp
hcra tnagele eht depsarg yllarutan sregnif eht erehw ylmrofinu nrow
.esuoh dlo eht fo dnof ylralucitrap saw zoR
.erutcurts tniauq ,llams eht dehcaorppa eh sa
.emit thgir eht t’nsaw won spahrep tahT .tsriF ehT
,drawot delggurts ev’uoy—ev’ew taht tset lanif s’worromot tuoba deirrow t’nsaw I“ ,deunitnoc ehS
diuqil suocsiv ehT
,deddap ylralimis eht tsniaga denilcer dna
.ecaps detacided a droffa ot elba gnieb fo lobmys a ,llew sa ,saw serutxif eht fo ycnenamrep ehT
,edisa tes ecaps ro ,evocla llams a dah yllacipyt semoH
.krims a htiw thguoht azzE
.sdnah gnihctulc sih ni ti ta derats tub ,ylisae ti thguac eH .zoR ta no gnileenk neeb d’ehs noihsuc eht dessot dna pu doots azzE
.elcyc s’oroS ni etal siht gnol erew sthgin eht dna
ecnetsixe deunitnoc eht derusne
.siht tuoba leef ot woh erusnu
mih devol ehs taht egdelwonk eht sa gnol sa
,yaw yna ni ,traeh sih zoR eraps ot rewop reh ni saw ti fI
dehcaorppa eh sa retsaf taeb traeh siH
”?yteiroton erised I tahT
”,evitaklat erom eb d’uoy ,evitisop gnihtemos gnikniht erew uoy fI
;htap tnereffid a nwod og ot reh ecnivnoc
regna ni stils otni deworran seye s’azzE
.ria esoidnarg on dah ecaps eht
.drawoc a eb ot flesmih wolla t’ndluoc eh
nosaer rehto on rof—ma I dna nac I“
.liat suounis ,kciht reh gniknalf dna
.htuom sti morf gnignah gnir revlis eht gnigniws nehw ssenetilop
,emoh eht ot krow rieht fo eceip a dna eman rieht dda ot gnitnaw nemstfarc fo egatrohs on neeb dah erehT
delwocs azzE ”.azzE nortaM ,oN“
.seenk reh dnuora gnilruc liat reh ,ti no tlenk dna
murcluf eht saw eH
.thgin eht otni gnitlem erofeb tuons nailitper sih fo tnorf ni ylfeirb gnuh tsim fo ffup niht A
zoR morf ecnatsid reporp eht tpek syawla d’ehS
;ega sti leef ot detrats ydob sih dah selcyc wef tsap eht ni ylnO
.enots eht morf ,enips sih pu
;stseug ynam era ereht nehw ro
.os ti deman taht werc yrev eht yb oroS ot thguorb lohocla fo elttob A
.reh esaelp ton did ecifircas deriuqer
.tsehc sih htiw neve rekconk revlis eht otno nehT
suorednop dna peed gnihtaerb sih dna
.tuons delbbep sih ta dehctarcs dna dias zoR
;meht delaever ehs sa selacs enotsdnas ,dellud sih gnikorts
.ecarbme reh denruter dna deerga zoR
yldas deripsus eH
,dias eh ”,og dluohs I
.elttob nialp a dna
.evael yllautca ot evom on edam tub
retaw ni seot eht gnippid sa elpmis sa eb dluoc gnisnaelC
,taht ekil neeb syawla dah tI
,dnah sih gnizeeuqs ,elims a htiw dehgis azzE ”,zoR ,hO“ .toof hcae fo eot eno gnilcricne gnir citsale na yb ecalp ni deruces
”.uoy ton yllaicepsE
,lanoisacco eht fo wolg rebma
.seye sih nepo ot dessarrabme oot saw dna ssensuovren dewollaws zoR ”.oN“
.ssilb derahs saw taht
.esu fo selcyciced morf dekcap dna drah saw seot depparw ylniht sih htaeneb htap ehT
,mraw eht saw noinapmoc ylno siH
sreh fo pot no dnah deregnif-ruof sih tes ylthgil zoR .pu mlap
rood eht morf emac kcilc dilos A
.deined eb ton dluoc ssensuoicsnoc fo tnecsa ehT
.ti esu ot roolf eht no tas eno dna
;dah syawla dray llams eht hguorht deohce taht dnuos lufnruom eht sa tsuj
.sgnillewd dehsinruf ylbatrofmoc tub natraps htiw
,mih dehtab ria detnecs
:rof gniraperp neeb lla dah yeht yad eht saw worromoT
,dial saw htap eht nehw devomer neeb dah seert oN
,lluks reh ta kciht detrats
,retrohs daeh a gnieb ,dna
,stluser s’worromot rettam on ,dne eht nI
,tuons delbbep sih fo sedis eht nwod swalc sih deggard zoR
mid denut erew yrtne eht ni sthgil ehT .tser kcab delgna
.gnilacs denehguot eht fo esuaceb sgel dna seot rieht no gnihton erow snairean ,yllanoitidarT
,reenigneoib ,remmargorp
,elpmis a saw cisab tsom ehT
;tcepser peed fo tuo tseug a gnihsaw
”,erutuf ruo fo noitcetorp tsetaerg eht eb lliw ycnaveleR“
kcab elttob eht tes ehS
,noissap nwo sih fo tiusrup sih saw ti roF
s’evocla eht otni detlem eH
.reisae yna noitaluger erutarepmet sih ekam t’ndid
swodniw ynniks ,llat owT
,sseccus ylekilnu na eb worromot dluohs ,dnA
.seenk eht troppus ot detplucs saw hcihw egde eht naht rewol
.tuo meht gnurw dna sgnipparw sih gnihsaw dehsinif azzE sa
htmraw s’nus eht gnisahc
.egduj a ekil mih erofeb doots rood eht dna
,dekramnu dna ediw a
”?morf siht si erehW“
.segnih delio-llew no yltnelis detovip ti neht dna
,trohs fo dray eht
”.srezinoloc tsrif eht yb thguorb saw ti eveileb I“ ”.neht ,evisnepxE“
,ni ti dloh ot deirt dna detsiser zoR
,etuor tcerid eht dediova d’eH
.yawa noitnetta reh denrut ydaerla dah azzE tub
”?taht kcip neve uoy did yhW“
dnah sih no pirg mrif reh deniatniam azzE
.noitacilpmi eht gnitset ,thguoht eh ,zoR ym roF
,srotsecna tneicna sih fo thguoht eh ,ylddO
gniyas no dennalp d’eh tahW
,hguoc a desserppus eh dna deralf slirtson siH
feirg tnetal sih egaussa ot dehca ehs tub
,sgniht lla rof noitanalpxe lanoitar dna ecneics ni feileb suoivrepmi rieht etipsed
,saw laem txen eht nehw tuoba yrrow ot dah ylno eh nehw emit a
.thgirpu mih gnihsup yltneg
,gnihcraes—mih dleh dna
.noitatidem ruoy gnitpurretni rof ezigolopa I“
.tnereffid saw emit sihT
”,taht naht retteb wonk uoY
ehca sgnul sih edam ria yllihc ehT
,meht fo sesnapxe tsav
.mih mlehwrevo ot denetaerht amora gnimoclew a hcus htiw detaicossa seiromeM
”.lliw s’nortaM ym ot edecca I“
,elpmis saw flesti tca eht hguohT
.moorhtab rehtona saw
.kaeps ot htuom sih denepo eH
”?emit tsal eno ,eb tsum tahw morf yawa em yaws dna yrt ot emoc“
emoclew ni nwod tuons reh detlit ehS
.edirts gnol yllarutan sih denetrohs eH
.retnec tcaxe s’gniraelc eht ypucco ot demees taht
;semit elbaremunni no neeb d’eh eno saw
,nisab gnisnaelc dellatsni yltnenamrep eht fo egde eht dnuora seot sih delruc zoR ,sthguoht s’azzE ot tnarongI
.srefiuqa tneicna yllauqe ot dnuorgrednu peed hcaer
”.tcejbus gnivil a desu ew emit s’tI
;rednu devil ehs edahs esohw seert eht fo krab eht ekil
?gnimocrevo saw eh noitrexe lacisyhp ton ti saw ,ro
,detceles eb dluow nortaM wen A
.elam yna ot rovaf taerg on wohs ot reh fo detcepxe saw ti ,nortaM sA
tsehc s’zoR tsniaga flesreh desserp azzE
”,kcis su ekam t’nseod taht epoh I“ .nosinu ni
.snoitpo eht gniredisnoc emit gnol a tneps evah I
mih dnimer ot dna
drawrof tcejorp eht gnivom taht tcaf ehT
.daeh s’azzE fo pot eht tsniaga yltneg tuons sih debbur dna detouq zoR
.troffe emos htiw pu deppets eH .derednow zoR
:fo liated yreve wenk eh taht
.flesmih htiw dna krow sih ni
dnuora neeb dah redro larutan eht fo sretsam esehT
.dedne htap eht erehw ecnediser pu ekat dluow ehs dna
.emoh gniog dna dnuora gninrut deredisnoc neve
.meht ot wolg suortsul a gninruter
.dah syawla ti sa ,mih gnidnuorrus seert tneicna eht fo shguob eht yb pu dewollaws
nisab eht erofeb roolf eht ot ti deppord
,detarepsaxe ,dias ehs ”,zoR ,nwod liat-dlo-pmil ruoy tiS“
,taht mih ot egnarts saw tI
;fo ecnerever ro ronoh ni
”?kovakS“ ”.knird a deen ew
.tuoba ”gnitanihcam“ neeb dah eh tahw fo
,tsitneics retupmoc yreve
.selacs gninniht eht gniltsoj
.enot reh ot eud ,evixelfer neeb dah cifironoh ehT
htap trid deroloc thgil
.sthguoht delbuort sih raelc ot tpmetta na ni
.sehcnarb gnignah wol hguorht
.seye s’nairean dlo eht otni pu dekool
,sregnif rieht gniniwtretni
.yldaed eb esiwrehto dluoc llihc eht taht erehwemos elbatrofmoc eb ot
”,dlo ytterp s’ti taht ssenkciht eht yb sseug nac uoy erus m’I“
.tcnitsni no ylpeed delahni eh dna
.kcor fo tseidrah eht neve nwod erow emit fo egassap ehT
dedne yeht sa gnirepat
,retsul dah llits selacs riehT
.yllufhtrim dias ehs
.yaw railimaf a ni
,evalcne eht fo sbal eht ni yltnatsnoc reh dnuora selam regnuoy raf erew erehT
tsiaw reh dnuorA
;slaem gnivres rof saw
,tsrif eht eb dluow ehs ,seY
.lioc tnagavartxe na ni dedne taht
sutats reh dna yrutnec a flah rof mih nwonk d’ehs
.moorhtab a dna smoordeb eerht ot del hcihw
.stsirw reh delcric ,latem suoicerp tnereffid a hcae
.thgis morf deraeppasid dna ,ylleb
.mih deyarteb spil dna sregnif sih fo sehctiwt eltbus tub ,peelsa nellaf dah eh thguoht ehs tnemom a roF
.evisulcxe yllautum saw nosaer rehtieN
.elam tnecseloda na fo sseniddig eht decneirepxe eH .delims zoR
elttob eht deppacnu ehs nehW
taht raen ecnartne yawllah a saw erehT
,remmah dlehdnah yb decalp
,spuorg llams gnitsoh rof dengiseD .trid
,seenk reh ot yawflah gnuh
.enildoolb eruP eht fo
,suoires t’nsaw ehs wenk eH
:snosaer yramirp owt rof detsixe teef eht gnipparW
,liat reh fo esab eht gnola rewol dils sdnah siH .delbmur zoR
,mih gnisnaelc no detsisni azzE dah erofeb reveN
,tsigolohcysporuen
.dne eht ni lufsseccus eb lliw ew
meht hguorht yaw sti denrub knird ehT
.mih delbmuh thguoht eht tub
.ssecorp eht ni seitniatrecnu llits erew erehT
”,semitemos em wonk uoy llew woh ekilsid I“
,suht ,dna flesreh nihtiw efil deretsof dah ohw
.htworg tneicna eht dnuora yllarutan detsiwt dna derednaem ti
ngised nairatilitu fo snmuloc decaps ylneve lareveS
deffuh azzE ”,elam tnedupmI“
.dial dah s’nortaM roirp taht
.seye sih denepo ylwols dna
stoor gnol sretemolik riehT .sknurt tneicna
erofeb sruoh owt tes dah nus enol s'tenalp ehT
.edisni mih dediug dna sih dnuora yltfos desolc sregnif reH
.nisab gnillif yldipar eht otni spord wef a deppit dna
,sgel sih pu gnipeerc
weiv euqserutcip A
;efil rehto yna fo dioved saw dort eh teerts devap eht dna gnineve etal saw tI zlaN yb
.htuocnu enilredrob saw ,saw ehs sa ,elam enol a esnaelc ot nortaM a roF
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ytidimuh hgih ro ,rehtaew toh emertxe rof erac ylralucitrap t’ndid eH
.tenalp eldarc-htrib rieht fo snosaes gnignahc ylbaroxeni eht hguorht
.flesreh dellits dna htaerb peed a koot ehS
”?ecaep ni etanihcam nac uoy os peelsa eb ot gnidneterP“
mid saw thgil ehT
,snosaes fo snezod roF
,pitregnif ot pitregnif ,flesmih fo senolc eerht eriuqer dluow seert eht fo emoS
,revewoh ,dlim llits saw erutarepmet ehT
.spil sih fo srenroc eht detfil
.ylwols delahxe dna
,tniop a ta dedne dna
,snoihsuc hsulp eht otni denilcer eH
.smra reh dessorc ehs sa
,efil gnillifluf dna gnol a llac dluow nairean yna tahW
,teiuq fo emit A .noitatidem
,laog ruo ,tnadnecsA eht ,tcejorp sihT
seye s’elitper llat ehT
redle sih sraey wef a saw ehS
.retnec ytic eht morf raf siht mih dniheb
.emit gnol a rof neeb sah ti sa
roloc emas eht fo cirbaf reivaeh fo triks esool a
,erutavruc yzal a htiw sevlesmeht no kcab dna nwod gniwolf
,doirep denifed yltcirts a retfa
.selcyciced rof ereht neeb dah ,meht egnahc dna ,meht kaerb ot erised ehT
.thguoht eh ,toh gnihcrocs ton s’ti tsael tA
segap eht no denozalbme eb dluow eman dna stroffe reh wenk ehS
snoitome sih deretsam ylkciuq zoR
.elims a htiw dnah reh dednetxe azzE
”.tsrif eht eb ot tnaw uoY“
.kovaks detropmi dah nortaM eht desirprus t’nsaw zoR
,fo erawa saw eh taht enoyna ro
.eugnot reh otno tuo deruop ylizal
,edab ehs sa did dna tlusni reh ta spil sih deggut taht elims hsipmi eht pleh t’ndluoc zoR
;rennam etamitni dna etaciled a hcus ni gnimrofrep saw ehs tey dna
,tuons sih fo tnorf eht ot regnif a htiw mih dehsuhs ehS
elkna s’zoR ta gnidnib fo dne esool eht deit taht tonk elpmis eht odnu ot nageb sregnif etaciled s’azzE nehW .wef a eman ot ,ssenevigrof geb ot ro evigrof ot ro
.zoR htiw stnemom lanif reh eb ton thgim eseht
gninoihsuc maof evitroppus eht otni knas eH
.kcalb dna nworb rekrad yb modnar ta delkcaps
,sreh otni dnah eerf sih koot ehS
niaga drawrof deppets azzE
.ycamitni dna ,noitcepsortni
.erac t’ndluow ehs t’nerew yeht fi neve tub
tovid htooms dna elpmid hcae
,railimaf ylgnitrofmoc ,mraw yltnasaelP
emit fo egassap eht dnatshtiw ot tliuB
.tenibac derood-elbuod ,egral a ot yaw reh edam dah azzE
,snoitatcepxe tnereffid ynam
.sruoh wef a naht erom rof eb dluoc ti ylno fI
tius dewollof eh litnu ,gnimsaps tsehc
.selttob eht sa esrevid sa erew sroloc esohw sdiuqil htiw dellif
.ecnayonna htiw dereviuq
.taht wenk eh ,dnim reh gnignahc on saw erehT
.ecneserp fo ecnenamrep a dah eh tub
,evorg eht fo ega eht aedi on dah eH
.tnadnecsA eht ni sutats gnireffid rieht fo esuaceb
,tresed eht fo roloc eht erew seye siH
.yria dna eltneg regnol on saw eciov reH
,tfos s’azzE nortaM
.krims desuma na htiw dias azzE
,talf ton saw hcneb ehT
.nisab eht morf yawa gnippets
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.teerts devap eht morf dehcnarb taht
esuaceb—taht tsuj gniod saw ehs ,thginoT
.ekuber reh ta dehcnilf yldetaleb dna
,tuo ylwols dna ni ylwols
.gnineve lanif siht emoc d’eh depoh dah ehs ,teY
edisa eugolonom lanretni reh tup azzE
?treva ot degnol eh tahw tuoba gnirb gnipleh rof denmad eb ro
”?noisiced ym detpecca ev’uoy ,oS“
.acitore iF-icS htiw detalupop yltsom si hcihw ,4002 ecnis tnuocca yrruFoS a dah sah dna snaretev yratilim rof lanruoj a ni dehsilbup
,amora ydaeh emas eht thguac zoR nehW
,mih dellif gnidoberoF
thgin yrev siht fo
.ecnelupo fo tnih a—enihcam ton
esoprup reh ni ytiralc a tlef ehS
.yawyrtne llams eht ni moor ekam ot llaw eht tsniaga kcab reh tup ehS
?su ot ,worromot ot ,thginot oT“
,evissam rieht dnuora hcaer ot
gnihtemos ebibmi ot detnaw neve eh erus t’nsaw eH .thguoht zoR
egral a evoba leehw dengised ylpmis a detsiwt zoR
,gnihtaerb sih no desucof eH
.deergasid evah dluow ehs
”,dnim ym degnahc ev’I“
.esnopser ni tuons gnol sih deppid dna
.selacs derab s’azzE ni detcelfer seldnac eht fo wolg gnirekcilf eht deciton eh dna
”.thginot em htiw yatS“
.’kcins‘ cillatem gnisaelp a htiw niard eht desolc tecuaf eht ot txen eldnah A
,evalcne eht ni renoititcarp secneicsoruen fo dairym rehto yreve dna ,noegrusoruen ,tsicitehtsorporuen
.liat a fo kcilf eht ni devil dah seert eseht
,tsenohsid eb ot em rof llew oot em swonk azzE
.kaep sti ta laturb ylralucitrap neeb dah nosaes toh eht dna
raer eht ta dnuorgrednu deraeppasid taht elubitsev yrots elgnis ,llat a
”?fo ronoh ni siht knird ew dluohs tahW“
.renroc eno dellif
.liat reh fo esab eht ot sedalb redluohs reh neewteb nwod dediarb sliat sti
.snoitartsinim etaciled tey mrif s’azzE rednu gnidaerps ylevixelfer seot
,srehtom rof ecnerever taerg ehT
”.sruoh lanif ruoy ni kcip dluoc uoy sgniht elbayojne erom era erehT“
mih dnuora gniraelc larutan a ot yawa llef seert ehT
”!haH“ .delbmurg zoR
.seye sih desolc dna
,dna gniliec eht detroppus
.rewsna eht gniwonk ydaerla ,deksa azzE
?zoR ,niaga od t’ndluohs dna dluohs I tahw em gnilleT“
.pil mottob reh ot puc eht tup dna kcab daeh reh detlit ehS .dias azzE
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,zlaN yb
,enif tsuj mih detius ria looc ehT
.mih otni esnes emos walc ot tnaw reh edam zoR semitemos tub ,netfo t’nsaw tI
.dnas eht dekcap dah seot fo sdnasuoht fo sneT
”?etanihcaM“ .seye sih denepo yllanif dah zoR
,I“ .vhiS ,dlrow rehtom rieht no ekilnu os
elims yoc a htiw mih dedrager azzE ”?yllaeR“
.muesum a ni yalpsid no eb ot devresed taht
gnihceeseb seye lufelod ,denrut nwod htiw lammam aes A
,seye sih fo roloc eht sa tsuJ
.noitadipert s’zoR deifilpma sihT
.reyalrednu gnitalusni
,eciohc reh htiw esae ta dna
.kcab htooms reh debbur dna
.yawa dnuow htap eht sa
,yrotsih tnadnecsA fo
,azzE ta dna dnah sih ni puc eht ta gnikwag neewteb dehctiws zoR
,emoh nwo ruoy gniretne nehw lewot a no meht gnipiw dna
.nisab eht ni delttes dah trid dna dnas fo stib wef a ylnO
,taorht reh ta dewohs euh ni rethgil yltniaf
,yad dna thgin neewteb serutarepmet etarapsid ehT
.enotrednu teews ylrevo ,egnarts a htiw
.mih ot puc a dereffo dna
,mlap a otno spord wef a desaet ehS
.reh retfa sriats eht nwod deddap dna
pat a ta dellif recuas egral
tcartxe eht fo tnecs eht yb dexaler ylneddus tlef ehS
nrets saw kool reH
latem gniparcs swalc detnulb
elims dicalp A .ylsuoiruc mih dehctaw dna
.hgual gnikcah a otni dehprom taht hguoc gnikohc a pots t’ndluoc dna
.yromem a ni tsol saw eh tlef zoR taht htiw dna
”tsaL eB toN llahS tsriF ehT“   yojne esaelP
,mih ot txen morf wollip erauqs ,pmulp a koot azzE
?flesti oroS ot dniknu os si ti fi worromot retfa su taert emit lliw woH
.eltnam sih emussa ot ydaer tey erew srosseccus sih elihw
.yticalas deniartsernu htiw
,pu seye reh dekcilf dna
.parw eot reyal elgnis eht hguorht depees dloC
,yrdnaylop fo syaw dlo ehT
,os“ ,deunitnoc ehS
”.zoR ym rof—tsenif eht ylnO“
,raW eneG cimsylcatac eht yb detatissecen
.zoR ,ecalp ym ni enoyna wolla ot esufer I“ ”.reetnulov I“
kcab eht ta tilps
.edisbus rennam sih ni noisnet eht was ehs
.zoR dnuora ylthgit smra reh depparw dna
krowdnuorg eht lla gnizilaer ylluf
.niard eht denepo dna yrd ot nisab eht fo pil eht no htolc fo spirts eht daerps ehS
,eno eht eb ot evah t’ndid ehs taht
.worromot reh detiawa tahw gniredisnoc yllaicepse
slipup kcalb-ecaps reh fo stils eht gnidnuorrus tsyhtema eht taht deciton zoR dna
,elttob nialp eht nialpxe seod tahT
/moc.yrrufos.zlan no skrow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,stelecarb dezisrevo owt
mih deknalf seert fo evorg larutan A
,tsrif ta ,ynam yb devol llew saw ehs rof
sgel gnol reh fo sevruc eht deppirg sgnirevoc gel lamreht kcalb ,reehS
eerf flesreh dehsup azzE
thgil ralucsuperc ni dehtab
.nisab eht fo pil eht no kcab seot s’zoR decalp dna
.slirtson decaps ylediw sih neewteb decalp yltcefrep
”?ytirailimaf…ym dnim uoy oD“
ylthgil desolc dehctal rood ehT
htgnerts a htiw dnah s’zoR dehsurc dna
,secalkcen dlog owT
.niard dna ,tecuaf ,nisab a htiw
.ti detterger dna
,htiw yalp ot mohw
,efil hguorht drawrof gnihsup fo selcyc xis-ytenin retfA
,seye eht ni reh kool ot elbanu
,serutaef prahs reh delknirw dna
”.eb dluohs I ebyam tub
dellevart eh daor ehT
!azzE“ .thgirpu tohs eh
.ezah elap a erob
.reh tidercsid ot gnihton did ti dna
.mih ta pu kool ot hguone kcab denael ehS .deilper azzE
,fo ngis a netfo saw morf ,derutcafunam ro ,detfarc saw nisab eht lairetam ehT
yppah eid dluoc ehS
.sregnif reh gnillits tuohtiw
,sredluohs sih no sdnah s’azzE tlef eh nehw
decuder yltnacifingis eb dluow ciffart eht denigami eh ,worromot retfA
.tsal eht eb ton dluow ehs
llef taht niar fo stnuoma llams eht dna
,daeh sih dewob zoR
.edistuo seert taerg eht fo segami dekovni taht amora wollem ,suoirbulas a delahni eH
”tsaL eB toN llahS tsriF ehT“ saw sihT
,dirca hcuot a ,rettib yltsom
.namstfarc retsam a fo krow eht neeb dah
.yletaciled ti deffins dna ti koot zoR
.eldarc dengised yllacificeps a otni deltsen eno hcae erehw
.dnuorgrednu del taht sriats eht dednecsed dna llah trohs eht nwod deklaw dna
emit a ta gel eno deird ehS
,mleh s’tcejorp eht ta zoR htiw tub
,triks trohs dna
:emoh siht ni gniht eno tnaem syawla thgil larutaN .thgileldnac
.daed eb dluow ehs worromot
”,sdnammoc nortaM ym sA“
ecneicserp demialc namstfarc eht fi desirprus neeb evah t’ndluow eH
sih tem ezag tsyhtema
.retfa erom ynam neht dna
yrots yrruf-non denrut yrruf ,noitcif-non eno dah sah ohw ,zlaN yb
.tuons sih koohs eH
,gniyasyan ruoy htiw em erob uoy erofeb ,tsriF“
.stsitneics reh fo eno sa ton
.ezis esnemmi ot werg dna
taht ni mraw peek ot ygolonhcet eht evah ton did sraeberof siH
,esuaceb tsrif eht eb lliw I ,zoR“
reh tsaltuo dluow eh ,noisiced reh yB
.daets ym ni ksir eht ekat ot esle enoemos gniwolla elicnocer tonnac I ,nortaM eht sa
,evacnoc ,deppid ti
.pets enots ,nwehhguor
,munitalp deremmah fo saw tI
,kaep sih ta niamer ot mih dedeen ehS .liaf ro—
gnir eht depsarg zoR
.ylisaenu reh dedrager eH
spuc yalc llams owt dekcip ehS
,kciht a dna sgniggel fo riap thgiew-muidem a ylno gnitatissecen
.yletum deddon zoR
daeh sih koohs zoR
;kcen tnagele reh ot gnulc
retaw eht otni sdnah reh deppid azzE
”,oot ma I“ ”.deracs ma I—
,reh ot hguorht teg ot elba eb dluow eh taht epoh llams eht ot gnilc ot elba neeb dah zoR
wollaws ot tluciffid ti dnuof eH
elims sselhtoot a otni denetfos serutaef reH
teews fo gnat eht
.waj ralugna sih fo egde denetfos ega eht gnola htrof dna kcab tuons reh fo pit eht dils dna
;stresed taerg eht fo
suonosiop denrut dah ti fi derednow dna
.ecniw mih edam dna mih deltrats taht
,reh fo esuaceb saw emoceb ylurt dluoc
.selcsum toof sih gnigassam detrats taht sregnif kcils eht yb detpurretni saw esnopser gnitalumrof siH .dediced zoR
.mih evrennu ot yllacificeps ydolem s’rekconk eht denut dah yeht nehw
.detareneg evah dluohs tnemevom llams eht naht reduol hcum demees mih deteerg taht dnuos ehT
.daeh sih fo wob a htiw dias eh ”,azzE nortaM ,seY“
,nworb peed erew selacs reH
.ylkeem denworf zoR
”.yrros m’I .em fo retteb eht gnitteg era snoitome yM“
,selacs suoicirbul s’zoR otni
reh fo yromem a htiw mih evael ot ytiliba reh ni ecnedifnoc etulosba dah ehs
.senob sih morf enots eht fo llihc eht gnivird
”tsaL eB toN llahS tsriF ehT“
.tfel zoR emit eht yb yrd enob eb dluow lairetam citehtnys eht wolfria elttil htiw nevE
s’zoR ot tuons reh desserp dna
.nortaM a sa sutats laicos nwo reh triks ot dna
.spmal nwod denut yb til yltfos moor egral a otni degreme yehT
.ti fo ssenevissessop eht dekil etiuq eh dediced dna
.ytuaeb s’azzE ta gnilims tsiser t’ndluoc zoR
.emoc ot feirg eht fo zoR eruc ot od dluoc ehs gnihton saw ereht wenk azzE
.detceles neeb dah azzE nortaM ,nehT
uoy htiw tsenoh eb nac I tuB“
,pu flesmih dehsup eh
,dnim sih deppils
”,yllautca ,togrof ,mhu
.suoiruc reh edam sdrow fo eciohc sih tub
dekconk d’eh ecnis desolc neeb dah seye siH
;evitarugif dna laretil
,krow ni ecnaillirb sih
.mra s’azzE dehcuot dna dedaelp zoR
.htap eht fo dne eht dekram taht
”.ereh yrassecennu era su neewteb scifironoH
gnillewd eht fo daeh eht
.stuc ot enorp erom
?ytinav fo tuo noisiced siht edam I taht gniylpmi uoy erA“
.mih ta yltfos dehgual ohw
,mih ta pu yltnelis gnizag elihw
ti yrt llew sa thgim I derugiF ?ton yhW“
.gnirednaw detrats dna tnemtrapa llams sih tfel d’eh ecnis reve esnet neeb d’eH
,deganam yllanif azzE
elbat nedoow egral a dnuora snoihsuc fo elcric-imes neknus A
.yawyrtne eht ni evocla eht ot detniop dna
.sedis sih ta pmil smra
.flesmih gnidulcni
.soobat larutluc gniyonna tuoba erac t’ndid ehs thginot ,revewoH
.oroS no ni detsixe yeht etats eht tey ton saw taht ,revewoH
selacs suortsul ecno reh derehtaew gnivah emit fo egassap eht etipseD
,citsilairetam yllacipyt ton erew s’nortaM
.yldesumeb deksa eH
.diulf suocsiv ylddo eht fo tnuoma esicerp a deruop ehs sa dehsols yldrah ecnatsbus ynobe ehT
.ruoh etal a hcus ta azzE nortaM gnibrutsid tnaem ti fi nevE
.pu seye sih dekcilf eH
yaw llams emos ni
.tset laer a tuohtiw teg ot gniog reve er’ew sa esolc sa er’eW“ ”.oN“
yawa denrut ehs sa derepsihw azzE
.daeh reh fo sedis eht ot esolc
”.klat tsal ruo ecnis emit emos neeb sah tI
lio eht gnigassam dehsinif d’ehS
,dnuorgrednu erew yeht taht won
.selkna sih tsniaga deppal taht retaw toh yltnasaelp eht otni meht decalp dna meht derab ehs sa
”.raeb nac ecneicsnoc ym noitpo ylno eht si
,yppah ylurt mih ekam ot od dluoc ehs tahw tuo wonniw dluoc ehs dehsiw ehS
.ecnenitrepmi lufyalp htiw deilper eh
.tnemrag reh fo cirbaf eht tsuj naht erom gnileef
thgie rof sriahc yb dednuorrus elbat nedoow regral A
,ylthgil nekat eb ot ton gnihtemos saw noitatidem s’azzE nortaM gnibrutsiD
,dnah reh tuo dleh neht
.elicimod a gniretne erofeb seot s’eno gnisnaelc fo ecitcarp larutluc eht saw siht fo tcudorpyb A
;seot sih dexelf dna daerps eH
?emoh ym ta em gnitisiv rof esneterp ruoy tuoba eil uoy od yhw
.emit a rof tsael ta—
.edisni dnah yb tliub neeb dah rood tnorf eht hguorht tif t’ndluoc taht gnihtynA
.evocla eht otni tliub taes hcneb tfos eht no gnittis
tnadnecsA eht gnihtyrevE
.enot reh ni eltbus ,dnammoc eht draeh eH
.seye sih desolc dna htaerb peed ,gnol a koot eH
.mmH“ .rehtegot sdnah reh debbur dna
,ngised dna ezis gniyrav fo selttob fo rebmun a saw swodniw ssalg latsyrc eht hguorhT
,ega dlo sih ni tfos erew selacs sih esuaceb ti did ylniam zoR
,oroS fo snoiger lairotauqe eht deteknalb taht stresed taerg eht ot esolc os
.ezag rebmos sih otni gnirats yb ylpmis
.krad eht tsniaga elttab lacilcyc sti ni dekcol
.gninokcer siht drawot azzE dereets yltbus dah taht
flesym gnicifircaS
”,raiL“ .dessih azzE
.derettug swodniw eht ni seldnac eht morf thgil ehT
;llems eht yb derewoprevo eson
.drawrof gnivom ylbaroxeni zoR tpek
.hctiwt liat dlo sih edam kcab gninrut fo sthguohT
gard ot demees emiT
,mih ta deralg dna dessih azzE
”,uoy eb ot evah t’nseod tI
.nehctik eht yb sedis owt no deknalf saw dnalsi llams a
ylpmis deritta saw ehS
.tnemetatsrednu elbidercni na neeb dah evisnepxE
;srewolfdliw gnimoolb eht morf roloc fo gnilknirps a htiw noitategev ybbuts
,niht sih revo og ot trihs eveels gnol dedooh
:nrettap nwonk on ot ylthgils decnad dna
.zoR ot flesreh elbmuh dluow ehs emit ylno dna tsrif eht saw siht taht reh deniap tI
,noissimbus ni eciwt eson sih deppid zoR
.emit a retfa deksa azzE
,sthguoht s’zoR ot ssecca azzE daH
stnemnorivne hsrah ni noitcetorp
.lewot desu ylsuoiverp eht no sdnah reh depiw ehs sa
”—eb t’ndluohs uoY
.srenwo ynam fo sdnah eht dna
.yrossecca noihsaf a sa dna
.trofmocsid s’zoR ta
.slirtson reh ot detfaw ecips fo etib dna
desolc llits erew seye s’zoR
.eugnot sih dehcuot ti tnemom eht sesnes sih detluassa kovaks eht dna
,tnemom etamitni siht ni ,revewoH
yltnelis detcerroc zoR ,tnemugrA
,emit eritne eht nortaM a neeb t’ndah ehs elihW
;tnecseloda na sa efil fo mih dednimer
”?gnikniht uoy erew tahW“
.ssecxe fo sehsiruolf htiw elddim eht ni erehwemos saw ecaps s’nortaM ehT
.meht gnihsaw elihw sdap dna seot sih egassam ot detrats ehS
.efil sih fo flah rof nwonk d’eh enoemos tisiv ot syawla
elamef yna fo gnissap eht rof gninruom lautir
,elttob eht decalper
tresed taerg eht deifed yehT
.htaeneb lenap reppoc eht otni nwod ti gnuws dna ,ti desiar
”,eurT lla fo doog eht roF“ .taht eveileb I
,seye sih ni ssendas fo tnilg a was ehS
,thginot evael mih tel I fI
.ti fo trap era uoy esuaceb dellifluf eb lliw ti
,elttob a dehctef ehs ,edisa lewot eht gnipporD
.sredluohs mils fo gnitfil dna
.tuops gnivruc drawnwod ,dehtuom
edisni eceip yreve ,revewoH
”,taht ot knird ll’I“ ”.su oT“
.dednuofbmud llits ,deremmats zoR
,snoitacilpmi dna selur
.zoR ta pu dekool dna
.eno tsrif eht morf tnereffid
,tsehc htooms reh revoc ot nwod gnippid
.htlaew ,fo kcal ro
”?ti si dlo woH“ ”.vhiS“
htaerb peed a ni dekcus zoR
,elam a sa mih detnaw ehs ,ylhsifleS
.zoR ot resolc deppets ehs sa deksa azzE
.ti deretnilps ,seiceps eht tuohguorht yltnereffid decitcarp
!deksa ylno uoy fi reetnulov yldalg dluow ohw sderdnuh era erehT“
,tsrif eht no desuap zoR
sredluohs s’azzE
,liat reh fo gniyaws eht dehctaw eH
.raW eneG eht fo tuollaf eht morf gnimmets slautir suoip dewollof llits yeht
.rehtegot gnihgual dna gnihguoc ,rehto hcae gnidloh erew yeht dna
.rood eht no eldnah detfarc yllufituaeb eht no dexif
.ti koot dna edisa wollip eht tes eH
gnipparw toof a fo dne eht ta kcip ot tuoba saw dna drawrof tneb zoR
,elam suolucitem a saw zoR
deeccus dluow stiusrup s’tnadnecsA eht hcihw yb
.noitadipert sih deleuf tahw saw ecnereffid tahT
”.zoR ,yats lliw uoY .oN“ .gnidiced
”.ot esoohc I naht
daeh reh fo llor a htiw ylduol dehgis ehS
.suotiucric neeb dah pirt sih ,teY
”.seitlucaf latnem rieht gnisol eb ot sredle tnadnecsA dedrager ylhgih ym fo eno ekilnu woH“
secnartne gnillewd yrots-elgnis ,tauqs wef a ylnO
pmal teerts decaps ylneve
,esu morf ynihs ,reppoC
.flesmih emalb dluow eh gnol woh derednow zoR
.nisab yrassecen naht regral eht otni llafretaw erutainim a ekil dewolf retaw mraw yltnasaelP
.flesmih naht reh ot dnik erom hcum neeb dah emit taht deveileb eH
.tug sih ta dewang ti dna suovren saw eH
.edicius elbuod a otni gninrut saw rehtegot thgin tsal rieht dna
”.enola ti hguorht reffus ot tnaw t’ndid I dna
spets enots cirtemmysa owt eht fo pot eht ta detiaw taht yawrood mils eht deknalf
snroh enotsdnas owT
gel hcae gnitfil
,troffe fo tib a htiW
,duts lartnec eht dnuora depparw sregnif owt htiw
reh dednimer selacs nat yksud sih
zoR ot pu deretnuas ehS
”?tnednecsA eht oT
reh dekcimim zoR
.noisiv reh fo srenroc eht ta gnitcelloc sraet
.nemuca sih no ylivaeh nael dluow nortaM txen eht dna
.raW eneG eht erofeb gnol
thgil elap yb til swodniw owt was dna teef sih fo tnorf ni morf pu dekool zoR
.ecarbme elbatrofmoc ylemerpus