,kaolc tsemraw sih ni desserd
,ydob s’lesaew eht tsniaga gnilioc selcsum
,elbon a erew yeht fI
.raelc saw noisserpxe sih ni niap ehT
.noisiced sih noitseuq ot trats mih edam tliug revenehw flesmih dednimer eh ,daeb a ylno saw tI
.kcohs sih laecnoc ot deirt hteZ
teef sih ot debmilc raugaj ehT
.syad wef txen eht rof hteZ no ylivaeh dehgiew
.tsehc s’revol sih no nihc sih tes dna dehgis lesaew ehT
dias hctiw eht ”,denraw erew uoY“
”.evig ot enim t’nsaw daeb ehT
.ytinutroppo doog a dnuof t’ndah llits eh dna
.lagelli morf raf tub ,deraef erew stra enacra rehto dna yrehctiW
,revewoh ,cigam enivid si tI
seirot sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.tanahoC ot em htiw kcab emoc dluohs uoY“
,ecitnerppa emos tsuj m’I dna ,ecnirp a er’uoy tuB“
”—hctiw ehT .yrros m’I …I
”,ssenhgiH ,ti dnammoc uoy fI“
daeb eht deveirter lesaew detsuahxe ehT
osrot s’hteZ ot wap ytpme sih gnivom ,dias eh
semalf eht morf egnis ot detrats ruf siH
?raW tseuqnI eht tuoba gniklat uoy erA“
.sredluohs eht yb hteZ koot dna
.kees uoy tahw uoy evig lliw I dna
,edisa sgnileeF .seY“  ”?yllaeR“
.ecaf sih no noisserpxe denrecnoc a
”.seY“    ”?ydaer uoy erA
.taeh elbidercni eht morf trofmocsid eht dnoyeb niap on leef ot desirprus saw tub
tnaem reffo s’ecnirp ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.sitabI fo steerts eht hguorht gniwolb
.daeb eht nelots d’eh thgin eht dah eh sa sdnammoc rieht wollof ot mih gnitcepxe
.mih sdrawot yaw sti nrub ot nageb erif nedlog fo enil niht a
,esproc eht ot ylfeirb detfihs ezag sih
.noom lluf eht fo thgil eht rednu elbisiv eb ylno lliw noitcarfer ehT“
.noom s’retniW morf nward si cigam ehT“
dewolla erew selcsum depmarc sih sa dnuorg eht ot yletelpmoc llef neht
,sniur gnilbmurc s’ytic eht nihtiw devil llits hctiw eht ylnO
.uoy er’uoy esuaceb laiceps era uoy ,hteZ“
,yawa gniklaw nageb hctiw ehT
,yltfos gnitnap saw hteZ
hctiw eht yhw dnatsrednu ot deirt hteZ
.lio gniremmihs eht otni swap rieht deppid hctiw eht sa
.snoitareneg hguorht nwod dna
,dezinagrosid hguohtlA
.knis stirips s’iX ees dluoc hteZ  ”.retsaM ,oN-
delbmert swap siH
.yks thgin eht decreip dna smra s’iX fo eno nwod enil a devrac thgil nedlog fo maeb a ,ecnO
,slatrom ot cigam hcus tnarg ot snosaes ylno dewolla droccA ehT .dezilaer eh
.htaehs sih dehcaer hctiw eht nehw
.noitulos rehtona tuo kees ot mih derrups noitarepsed s’iX fo yromem eht tub
.tcaer ot etal oot saw ti litnu
.redluohs s’hteZ no wap a decalp raugaj ehT
.lufnruom dna gnitnuah
.esuoh eht fo tnorf ni mih rof detiaw hctiw ehT
,evloser dewener gnirrups thguoht taht htiW
”?gnigneva uoy era ohW
kaeps ot deirt eh ,etarepseD
,krow ot siht roF“
saw sihT     .hguone saw taht
.ylmrif gnisserp dna
,mih dnuora elcric a decart emalf ehT  ”.on-
”.evila mih peek lliw I tuB
?gnihtyna dnuof uoy evaH
”?ytic yrev siht oT
”.seye ruoy ni flesym esol thgim I kniht I ,won nevE
”!oga sraey 003 saw tahT
.mih yrrac dluoc sgel sih sa ylkciuq sa sniur gniyaced dna seert esned eht hguorht gninnur
.doolb s’rehtafdnarg ym ot deknil ylbacirtxeni si daeb eht
”?emoh teg uoy nehw eno rehtona teg tsuj uoy t’naC
,moorkcab eht nI
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.retnec eht ta ecalperif egral a derahs taht smoor ralucric-imes owt otni dedivid saw emoh s’uobirac dlo ehT
meht fo htob dnuora decselaoc sthgil deroloc ,gnilriws fo yarra gnilzzad a
”.nomannic erom esahcrup
”,efil dnetxe nac cigam enivid ylnO .sey ,hO“
.ecno ta gnipmarc ylneddus saw elcsum yreve fi sa tlef eh dna
.riapersid fo etats a ni tsom
,sevreser s’oetS raugaj eht dewohs hteZ elihW
.sdoow krad eht hguorht detnirps eh elihw
,detlem mih dnuora wons eht sa
gnihtolc dna ruf sih ta erot selbmarb dna sehcnarb dloc ,htap eht gnirongI
,kcalb ro etihw fo edahs a saw hcaE
,noisserpxe reh ni ecilam htiW
,wap derujninu sih ni deppirg llits saw diarb ehT
,sredluohs s’hteZ desaeler iX
,tnetni s’hctiw eht revetahW
”.suoiruc tsuj m’I
derewol efink eht nehw bmun tlef sregnif sih tub
.regnad fo esnes eht ot gniyalp ,derepsihw eh
.yawa thgir ecalap eht ot regnessem a tnes evah dluow ew
noitats s’iX fo enoemos taht dednamed selur esoht fo enO
.sevren sih elttes depleh hcihw
” .daeb eht nruter ot deen I
.erofeb decneirepxe reven dah
,osrot sih fo retnec eht nwod efink eht gard ot nigeb flesmih tlef lesaew eht
,kcen rieht no erow yeht diarb rehtael eht ta dehctulc hctiw ehT
.gniod neeb d’yeht tahw ot denruter ohw
,enod saw ti nehW
,kool ot seye s’hteZ truh tI
,ytinav saw ti wenk eH
.dirgiV ssorca deklaw sdog eht nehw
.daeh sih koohs raugaj ehT
.nus eht fo roloc eht wolg ot nageb retnec sti ta daeb etihw eht dna
evah sa ,eltnam enivid a deirrac ecno rednuof s’ylimaf ym ,selbon tsom sA“
,prahs saw edalb eht tub
”,ti koot I taht wonk reven nac eH“
,emoh rieht ta devirra eh nehw dna
”.uoy truh ot tnaw t’ndid I
taorht sih morf emac taht eciov eht
.elbinrecsid tahwemos
.yks thgin eht fo srats eht gnitcelfer seye yssalg
,sredwop suoirav htiw dellif
.esiarp eht ni delever lesaew ehT
.htaenrednu lesaew nommoc eht gnilaever
,kaeps ot delggurts eH
esolc deppets hctiw eht
,seenk sih ot despalloc hteZ
.erew netfo srevol yaw eht ni rehto hcae dnuora depparw erew
nisab nialecrop eht no llef seye sih dna
.nihc sih rednu delzzun hteZ
sevlehs worran fo swor dleh moor gnol eht fo edis rehto ehT
sih ni dias xof yltrop eht
.sredluohs dna kcen s’enilef eht dnuora smra sih depparw hteZ
gninefaed demees gnirettahs nisab eht fo dnuos ehT
,desuap lesaew ehT
taht od ot yaw tseisae eht dnA
,elbat rehtona otni delbmuts hctiw eht sa
:suoiruc gnihtemos deciton eh ,dekrow yeht sA
.nemodba rewol sih ssorca hsag hcni eerht a erot efink eht sa tuo deirc hteZ dna
.edisni pets ot flesmih decrof eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.retsaM ,em tel ll’uoy fi hcraes nac I“
.trapa ecnatsid trohs a regniferof dna bmuht a pu dleh eH
.tevlev ni dehtaehs leets ekil
.xaler yllanif ot
.ssenkrad eht morf mih ta gnireep erew seye dnasuoht a fi sa
.reggad eht desaeler iX
.hcaer nihtiw elbat eht no gnitser
.meti na hcus ecalper ylisae dluoc dna ,elbon a saw iX
elihw gnis ot nageb dna
.meht dellik dah eh thguoht hteZ
.seye sih treva ot mih wolla ton dluow yeht tub
”.sdnuow ruoy enimaxe ot deen I .hteZ ,llits dloH“
,digir dnats ot decroF
,tnessa sih deddon eh nehW ”.kaeps ton oD
,eciov sih fo lortnoc desaeler yehT
,ekatsim sih xif ot hcum os detnaw eH
”.evila denrub neht
.emit on detsaw hteZ
,snoitpo sih tuoba thguoht eh sA
.nomannic dna etalocohc fo hcraes ni pohs eht ot emoc tsrif dah ecnirp ehT  .edart wen dna
”?eulav latnemitnes sah tsuj ti ,oS“
.stnecs tnasaelp htiw moor eht dellif seraw citamora ehT .saet dna ,secips
,won rof tsael ta ,dezilaer eh dnA
,taorht nwo sih ot edalb eht gnidloh saw lesaew eht ,sdnoces nI
noitceffa s’iX dna gnileef tahT
.ecalap eht ot denruter yltnatculer iX
.kcab sih otno lesaew eht depleh ylluferac dna meht neewteb ecnatsid eht derevoc ylkciuq iX
?ti elots enoemos fi neppah dluow tahW“
.ytic eht sdrawot kcab deklaw yeht sa raugaj eht tsniaga nael ot decrof saw eh dna
yltfos delworg raugaj ehT  ”.ecnirP ,oN“  ”?hteZ“
.ti otni retnaced eht deitpme neht
,gnirehtid sih desnes yeht nehW
.niks sih ni tuc wollahs a evael dna
”,erup dna tfos os ,wons eht ekil si ruf ruoY“
,ruf detniona eht detanimulli thgilnoom eht reverehw
,noitasnes gniknis a htiW
,muroced fo snoitatcepxe hgih ot ytilibon lla dleh llits dliug eht
mih dniheb spetstoof eht raeh ton did eH
”.ytic eht htaenrednu sbmocatac tneicna eht hguorht depacse yehT“
,seveiht yb derever tsom dog eht
:noitautis eht yfitcer ot yaw eno ylno saw ereht dezilaer lesaew eht
,htiw revo siht teg ot regae tub ,niatrecnu llitS
,noitatirri ni gnihsal liaT
:retniw fo thgin tsrif eht no gnas semitemos stseirp nevlow eht
”?suoregnad ti si woH“
,rewop koot yeht ,tseuqnoc hguorhT
”.em llet tsum uoy
.edisni delbmuts iX delevehsid a nehw
.demaelg seye s’hctiw ehT
.rehtegot enola erew yeht nehw enod syawla dah eh sa
***   .ti denruter eh nehw
.meht wener ot dias saw ecneulfni sih dna
regnorts worg ot gninnigeb taeh gniretsilb tlef eh dna
,mih denioj ylkciuq hteZ
.ydob sih revo gninnur erew swap dna sregnif ,nooS
.hhS“  .raugaj eht egdelwonkca ot sdrow eht mrof ot eganam t’ndluoc eh dna ydob s’hctiw eht no detaxif erew seye s’hteZ
,dekcohS  .tenibac nehctik dezisrevo na hguorht gnigammur nageb swap dna
”?esle gnihtyna od ot deen t’nod I
,dloc eht ni doots eh gnol woh yas t’ndluoc eH
.meht ta deralg eh dna
,rorret ni demaercs eH
.thgilerif eht ot pu ti dleh yeht sa
”?deb ruoy ni spahreP
ezis eht tuoba saw ti ,enob fo edaM
.sdrow eht dnif ot delggurts eh
,rethgirb worg ot demees ti ,tcaf nI
…daeb eht ,hteZ“
,cigam eht derujnoc I .eno si erehT“
.semalf lacigam eht yb dehsinrat
.hteZ gnisiarp nehw desu eh enot tnagorra-no-gniredrob-tnedifnoc eht ni
nihc sih deppirg iX
.lio eht otni desufni neeb dah sevlesmeht sthgil eht fi sa
,niragiaT sselwalf ekops eH
.raugaj eht ot revo gnilbma
,gnirpS ot reyarp etarepsed a dezilanretni eH
noitartsurf fo trons trohs a
.thgir yb enim si tI“
.llew od dluow uoy wonk I
”.yadot od ot krow erom hcum si erehT .tneiciffe tub
.kconk ot evren eht pu dekrow
.noitseggus eht otno tpael iX
.denialpxe hctiw eht
.eciov rieht ni ecnerever a saw erehT
.dilavni si niagrab ehT“
daeh sih koohs eh tub
.krow rieht did sregnif elbmin elihw
!oN“ .dennuts saw hteZ
”,cigam eht erujnoc won lliw I“
,mih ta dehgual yehT
,hteZ ta dennirg yeht
,deriuqer hctiw eht tnemyap revetahw tpecca
.devomnu saw ,revewoh ,hctiw ehT
seltnam enivid rieht deirrac ohw
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
”,yrruh ot deen eW“
ti denioj noos sehtolc rehto siH
.tliuq eht revo swap sih gninnur nageb dna
,deksa yllanif eh ,ecnelis fo sdnoces wef a retfA
,sehcuot latnedicca fo seires a
desaeler eh erofeb sdnoces gnol lareves rof
wollip sih htaenrednu daeb eht edih ot noitom eht gnisu
,eniw fo elttob a erahs ot thgin taht denruter dah iX nehW
.tsehc s’lesaew eht fo retnec eht otni
,evom dluoc eh thguoht hteZ naht retsaF  ”.mih esaeleR“
.tuo gniyrc morf pots ton dluoc eH
.emit ekat lliw tI“
.dnif dluoc yeht ytilibon eht fo rebmem yreve derethguals dna
,yrrow ro esirprus morf rehtehW
.hctiw a yb detpmet gnieb rof uoy evigrof nac I
.diarb a mrof ot rehtegot sdroc rehtael lareves
.ylrae tfihs sih dne ot deksa dna
.evila ecalp siht evael reven dluow eh taht won dezilaer eH
.detnuah gnieb rof
erofeb xnyl eht ot ygolopa na derettum oetS retsaM
.seye s’hteZ otni kcab dekool raugaj ehT  ”?hctiw a …ro
”?thgir lla uoy erA“
srae sih tlef lesaew ehT
sdniw retniw digirf eht degdelwonkca kaolc denil-ruf a ylnO
.dah revol suoiverp sih sa
.seert daed fo mih dednimer yehT
.yebo ot desufer selcsum sih
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.hteet prahs s’iX sa hcum sa
.gnidliub enots gnilbmurc a fo tnorf ni rood nedoow dekoorc a fo tnorf ni doots hteZ
,ot detnaw mih fo trap A
.daeb eht dleh eh ,wap rehto siH
,daeb eht deiduts eh sA
,hctiw eht yfsitas ot demees sihT
”.uoy tcetorp dluow I
,tnemom gniyfirret a roF
.deniamer diuqil ylio eht ni noitcelfer rieht tub
.hteZ ot kcab noitnetta rieht gninrut dna
.enot eht ni noitseuq on saw erehT ”.hctiw eht er’uoY“
.ngised etacirtni ,deliated ylenif a htiw devrac dna
.eciov sih otni reggaws lausu eht fo emos gnicrof ,dias eh
saw ti dah I niatrec ma I emit tsal ehT
.pih sih ta reggad eht werd eh dna
.siht od t’nod esaelP“
sgniK niragiaT fo licnuoC eht htiw taertne ot htron tnes
.nosrep doog a si iX
ezilaer ot tnemom a hteZ koot tI
.repinuj fo tnecs ydoow eht deirrac diuqil suocsiv eht fo tnemevom hcaE
,htron raf os erar erew sraugaJ
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.rewot a neeb ecno dah tahw ni
saw srae rieht neewteb rufdaeh yarg trohs tsdima gnisiR
,tsehc s’raugaj eht ta dedaenk hteZ
.skeehc sih nwod gnimaerts nigeb ot sraet desuac taht niap lanoitome eht saw ti tuB  .niap saw
.maets otni yawa gniliob
,lio eht ni detarutas llits
,wap sih deppord raugaj ehT
.flesmih htiw evil ot elba eb ton dluow eh
– iX rof laiceps gnihtemos eb ot saw detnaw d’eh llA
.kaolc sih fo psalc eht netsafnu ot nageb hteZ
,ryC rohtarB yb ”taoC retniW ehT“
.gnihtyreve denialpxe taht fi sa
.fo duorp neeb evah thgim oetS retsaM tnemugra fo dnik eht saw tI
.meht ot dlihc deniart-hctiw sih rednerrus ot desufer relur eht esuaceb
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.no dedneped eb dluoc iX taht wenk won eh ,tuB
dehsilbup ylsuoiverp saw ohw
.nees eb regnol on dluoc ecnirp eht nehw knas traeh s’hteZ
.yltfos dias hctiw eht ”,gnirpS“
,sehctap ni yawa nrub ot detrats
gnivaew erew yehT
,raW tseuqnI eht fo dne eht raeN
.mih fo tnorf ni elip a ni
,lessev a tem reven dah hteZ .ytilibixelf dna
,smeti regnarts raf dleh wef a tub
,stnemom wef a retfA
.regnif tsellams sih fo elkcunk tsrif eht fo
evol I tahw tuB .lufituaeb era seye ruoY .lufituaeb saw ruf ruoY
”,dlihc eht ton tuB
tsirw sih nwod pird ot nageb doolb dna
”.eugnot ruoy htiw did uoy tahw em hcaet tsum uoY“
leef mih gnikam ,ruf fo hcni yreve detaoc dna
.drow hcae morf gnippird monev
,erugif citelhta sih ffo dewohs taht gnihtolc enif ni desserD
,krow rieht enimaxe ot kcab deppets hctiw eht ,ecirhT
”.dedne sah ssenisub ruO .yob ,evael woN
.ot elba neeb eh dah tuo deirc evah dluow eh
,ti ot dnuob rewop suorecros eht sediseB“
ryC rohtarB yb ”taoC retniW ehT“
naorg deniap a draeh eh nehT
.hsulb sih ees dluoc retsam eht fi derednow dna gninrub
.skoob yvaeh fo noitcelloc a ni ydob reppu rieht fo tsom gniyrub ,dnuorg eht ot nwod stnetnoc sti dna ti dellup neht
.taht lla egnahc dluoc taht nalp a dah eh ,revewoH
derumrum raugaj eht
,elbat a otno nisab nialecrop egral a decalp hctiw eht
.mih ta kcab dereel hctiw eht
.tevlev rieht fo deppirts sreltna yldnips fo riap a
dellepmoc tlef lesaew eht snosaer eht erew
.dnatsthgin sih dniheb hcraes ot gnidneterp yb tliug sih pu derevoc lesaew ehT
,hctiw ro retsac enur eno tsael ta deyolpme seilimaf lufrewop ynam ,tcaf nI
,erots llams a fo moorkcab eht nI
.sdrawkcab pets ylwols ot nageb dna
”,elzzum ym morf emoc ton lliw tI“  .dias hteZ
”.retsaM ,esruoc fO“
,niap ni debborht ydob eritne siH
.dliug ruoy rof rodassabma na eb dluoc uoy kniht llits I
ecalperif renroc eht ni ezalb A
,morf emoc dah hteZ noitcerid eht kcab gnikool neeb dah ohw ,iX ,teiuq neddus eht tA
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
,gnihtolc rehto sih fo pot no sehtolcrednu dedlof sih gnicalp saw hteZ sA
,dehsimelbnu dna erup niamer lliw ruf ruoY
mih rof tfel dah yeht llA
.nrub ot nageb gnihtolc siH
.gnineve eht rof deb sih ot deriter yllanif hteZ
raugaj a dna lesaew deliat-gnol a
,sruoy fo gnihtyna dnif ot erew ew fi taht uoy erussa I“
.mih ta kool hteZ edam dna
.elkcuhc yhctarcs a dehgual hctiw ehT
,sllaw ytic eht morf klaw s’ruoh na tuoba saw eH
N“  .dluoc eh ezilaer ot desirprus saw dna
,meht fo owt eht neewteb dekool xof ehT  ”.pleh lliw I“
.revo saw ti dezilaer eh sa sbos neewteb ylpeed dehtaerb eh tub
,denrub neeb dah ti
,dias yeht ”,meht nrub yehT“
.dehcuotnu saw niks siH
,sdneirf rieht fo seman eht rof derutrot erew
”.rewop sih fo emos no ward ot nrael dluoc enoyna ,ti htiW
deredduhs enilef eht ,nooS
.ecirp yna teem ll’I“
.ssem ykcits derahs a htiw noitaicerppa sih gniwohs
.desaet lesaew eht
”.lesaew eht evaeL“  .nwo sih ton saw
,dehcterts dna kcab sih dehcra eH
.swap gnorw eht ni suoregnad yrev eb dluoc ti
?elpoep ruoy ot did eh tahw wonk uoy oD
”...gnihtemos wonk uoy fI
.noitasnes lacisyhp eht ot dnopser ot nageb ydob s’hteZ nehw neve
.seiruxul hcus fo noitceles detimil a yrrac did pohs eht dna
,kcurts neeb sah niagrab ehT“
”?ruf sih rof gnirac no ecivda nam gnuoy emosdnah a hcus evig hctiw dlo na dluohS“
regnif a desserp eH ”.ereh si
.daerht enacra na yb detcennoc won era eW
,iX“ .mih depleh iX
wols ni sregnif rieht gnivom nageb hctiw gniralg eht ,ecnelis fo tnemom a retfA
,hcranom nrehtuos lufrewop a fo nos driht eht saw tanahoC fo lipiX ecnirP
.em rof siht od ot dedeen uoy thguoht uoy taht si struh tahW
,mih tsniaga nwod dna pu ydob eritne s’hteZ detfil eh sa thgiew ni tfihs eht eciton ot demees yldrah ecnirp ehT
s’raugaj eht derongi lesaew eht ,troffe htiW
,rehtegot dehtirw lesaew derruf-etihw dna
delrans hctiw eht ”,flesyM“
.niaga flesmih tuc ot decrof saw hteZ dna
,lufituaeb dna riaf saw dlihc eht tuB“ .dias yeht
.krow rieht morf pu gnikool ton ,dias yeht ”?daeb eht gnirb uoy diD“
.niks sih otni gnitib latem dloc eht
.swap sih otni nisab eht tsurht neht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,esaelP“ .mih truh ot saw
,detartnecnoc ,litnu
,denodnaba tlef eH
.dehsinav yltpurba semalf eht dna
.yad remmus toh a no thgilnus fo sserac eht ekil
ssik a htiw raugaj eht detcartsid neht
.evalcnoc retniw launna rieht gnirud
,tliug yb demusnoC
!daed lla era truh yeht elpoep ehT“
sraey owt rof ytic eht ot egeis dial yehT“
.sgnaf dna swalc htiw gniraet
retnaced ssalg a deveirter yeht ,gninnirg llitS
,kcab daeb taht teg t’nod I fi ,hteZ
yvaeh saw nisab ehT
.knab wons a fo esab eht ta pots a ot gnimoc
,desuap raugaj ehT
doolb eht otni sessap rewop taht fo emoS“ .denialpxe eh
.daetsni daeb eht ta kool ot flesmih decrof eh neht
gnidliub yrots elgnis
,dednuof neeb dah sitabI emit eht yb dna
,deworran seye s’raugaj ehT
,oetS retsaM derongi eH
.hctiw eht htiw sekatsim ynam edam d’eh wenk eH
.daeh sih fo kcab eht nwod gniliart rufdaeh fo sdiarb niht ni erow raugaj eht sdaeb eht no desucof eH
tcaer ot ecnahc on dah hctiw eht dna ,dnuorg tfos eht tsniaga dnuos on edam
,daed yal hctiw derebmemsid eht dna
,em htiw emoc ot tnaw uoy fI
,odnecserc a dehcaer gnos eht nehW
,taerht s’hctiw eht fo seiromem yb detcartsid
.erehwesle saw noitnetta s’oetS retsaM dna
daeb eht werdhtiw hteZ ,yltnatculeR
.mih tsniaga delbmur iX
,edistuo mih derehsu hctiw ehT
”.llams yrev si tI“
hteZ retfa eciov gnidnammoc ,yhctarcs a emac ”,ni emoC“
,deifisnetni gnikamevol rieht fo ycnegru eht sa dna
.noos revo eb lliw evalcnoC ehT“
:yrlewej lausunu fo seceip lareves erow osla raugaj eht
”?sehctiw ot od sraugaj eht tahw wonk uoy oD“
.lesaew eht ni gnihtemos dezingocer yltnerappa eh sa
,retal sruoh wef A
,hctiw a tuoba deksa uoy nehW“
.reggad s’iX fo egde eht dnuora depparw sregnif rednels nwo sih
.wap sih ni dehctulc llits diarb rehtael eht ta gnirats saw raugaj eht dezilaer hteZ dna
,llef ytic eht nehW
.gnissim saw ti ezilaer neve ton thgim ecnirp eht ,tcaf nI
,dehca ydob eritne s’lesaew ehT
.nretnal edisdeb sih rednu ti denimaxe dna
wols saw ssenisub nehw semitemos dna
.derettacs srovivrus eht
.rae thgir sih dniheb tsuj gnilgnad
,seye s’raugaj eht otni dekool eH
N“  .yldetniop dias oetS
,mih ot pu thguac wohemos dah hctiw eht demussa eh
.lwob eht revo revoh ot nageb yeht
daeb eht dnuora tsif a gnisolc ,dias yeht
.kcen s’lesaew eht fo spin neewteb
.noicipsus htiw worran seye
”.regnad ni eb dluoc tanahoC fo lla
,daeh sih koohs hteZ
,thginrevo semitemos
.sdne fo rebmun yna ot taht tiolpxe dluoc tsinacra nA
.tsum uoy fi lleps eht dnE
.deruces neeb dah daeb eht erehw
,reilrae sedaced delttes neeb dah etupsid nepo eht elihW
.hteZ ta yllufgninaem dekool eH
”.trosnoc yreve fo yvne eht eb dluow uoy …ruf sihT
,sevil cigart del netfo esohc gnirpS esohT
.eltit a hcus ecitnerppa na gnitnarg uoy etaicerppa t’ndluow dliuG s’tnahcreM ehT“
,sniur eht fo tsom demialcer ydaerla dah tserof eht
.retsam eht no ezag sih gnittes yllanif
demees txen deneppah tahw
.deretla eb nac ti tub ,tnesnoc lautum tuohtiw dne tonnac lleps ehT
htworger fo ytied a saw gnirpS taht thguat hcruhc ehT
.gnigavlas dnoyeb saw ,revewoh ,ruf siH
.setuor edart wen eht hsilbatse pleh ot tanahoC ni evitatneserper dliug a deen I
,deb eht no nwod tas neht
.sserttam derehtaef sih tsniaga desserp eb ot flesmih dewolla lesaew deveiler eht ,enod deed ehT
,emac sraugaj eht nehT
gnihtolc sih hguorht tuc ot hguone peed gnisserp
.deirrownu demees iX
.yfitnedi t’ndluoc hteZ hcihw fo ynam
.seitic tsetaerg s’dirgiV fo eno neeb dah sitsaB
,ta gnitnih saw hctiw eht tahw dezilaer hteZ
.srebmem htiw wollof ot erew selbon slocotorp fo mrof eht ni yltsom
oetS dehcaorppa eh nehw ssenlli ngief ot evah ton did lesaew eht
,diarb eht gnidloh dnah eht desiar yehT
.ti morf knird ot deen t’ndluow eh depoh eH .top rebmahc
.moolrieh ylimaf a si tI“
”,enil ruo ni srehto lareves
,yad eht rof pohs eht desolc oetS nehW
.iX truh ot mih esu ylno dluow yeht
.iX ,daeb ruoy tuoba yrros …m’I“
hctiw eht ot ti dednah eh ,detpmorpnu ,dna
daeh sih koohs eH
tnepres derehtaef devargne eht dna
,reilrae seirutnec eerhT
daeb etihw elgnis eht no daetsni gnisucof
”.noitomorp ruoy rof gninoititep neeb sah oetS
,meht dnuora derutseg yeht
”,oetS retsaM ,seigolopa yM“
.nmelos enot ,dias eh ”,hteZ“  .cinap
.tsrif ta evom ot elbanu saw eh
”.degreme tsuj dah taoc retniw ruoy fi sa
,roolf enots s’tnorferots eht gnipeews saw eH
”,snosaes eht fo eno rof lessev a emaceb …uoY“
.drocca nwo sti fo sdoow eht hguorht kcab egdurt ot nageb ydob sih dna
taoc retniw etihw-wons sih revo denwaf raugaj eht yaw eht tub
.regnif eltneg a htiw mih dehsuhs raugaj ehT   ”—uoy
s’hteZ gnihcraes
.emit fo tuo gninnur saw eH
.llih a fo tserc eht ta
,ytidun sih ees ot sdoow eseht ni esle eno on eb dluow ereht wenk lesaew ehT
***  .thgin digirf eht otni derutnev neht
,redneg rieht neve ro ,eman s’hctiw eht wenk eno oN
.tnemyap sa ti dednamed dah
,dne tneloiv a ot emac ti nehT
,dezad saw lesaew ehT
,ruf reh rof redwop detnecs a tceles xnyl a gnipleh saw ohw
,stroffe citegrene
– ti otni devrac neeb dah taht erutaerc eht ezingocer t’ndid hteZ
,neddus os saw esuoh s’hctiw eht dniheb erugif dewodahs a fo ecnaraeppa ehT
:ereht ees ot detcepxe reven d’eh gnihtemos was hteZ dna
.ecraf eht ot dne na dellac yllautneve oetS retsaM
.gnieb ruoy dna lliw ym neewteb dnob a detaerc sah lleps eht os dna
,lleps eht gnirud desu d’yeht
eno siht piks nac uoy
.elixe desopmi-fles ni evil ot esohc yeht yhw wenk eno on
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,mih dracsid dluow iX ,wenk hteZ ,dnA
.efil sih rof geb neve ro tuo yrc regnol on dluoc eH .osrot sih otni
.thgin eht otni nar neht
”,tub ,daeb a tsuj saw ti flesym decnivnoc I“
.deggeb eh ”,esaelP“
snoitaler devorpmi fo tcepsorp eht rof regae neeb dah oetS retsaM tub
”.dellik em evah ylbaborp d’yehT
.tnemevom ykrej a ni
,tceffe derised rieht dah sdrow siH
retnab lufyalp dna ,selims evitruf
,srehtaef htiw denroda sserddaeh elpmis a
lavorppa sih deffuhc raugaj ehT
.eciov ”remotsuc tluciffid“
”,gnihtolc ruoy evomeR“
”.elbissop ton s’tahT“
,slessev rieht rof ylno neht dna
,kaolc sih dedracsid ecnirp ehT
.raew I sdaeb eht fo eno gnissim ma I“
,selbat dehctamsim fo elbmuj a saw moor tnorf ehT
,xaler ot raugaj eht detcepxe hteZ
,tnemom gniyfirret a rof dna ,ecneloiv fo tca neddus eht gniwollof ecnelis a saw erehT
.truh lliw lesaew eht ,hO“   ”.mih truh t’noD“
.eeyolpme rehto yna htiw gnitcaretni erofeb rebmem dliug eht egdelwonkca
.modgnik rieht fo secips demaf eht erew sa
.egnahc gninethgirf ,esnemmi
senil lellarap wollahs tuc ot nageb dnah gnideelb s’hteZ ni edalb eht
.dessim dah yeht secalp otni lio erom raems dna nruter ot ylno
.dlrow nwo rieht fo seiradnuob eht demrof lasuora rieht fo stnecs delgnim eht
***  ”.snrecnoc ruoy fo tsael eht eb dluow ruf ruoy
,slatem suoicerp fo edam ecalkcen daorb a
,regnad ni ylimaf s’raugaj eht tup dah eh fI
ot emac I …ew gninrom eht
.ytilibon eht tsuj ton ,cigam lennahc ot nrael dluoc enoyna ecalp A
.hguorht tuc d’eh cinut eht ffo leep ot decrof saw eh sa
,ecno dehcnilf eH
,daetsnI .ygolopa na reffo ot deirt hteZ
”.meht no ytip koot sdog eht fo eno dna
yojne esaelP  .yrruFoS
.gnihcraes saw ezag siH
iX ot gnihtyreve
dezilaer lesaew eht
.lesaew eht ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut
,tnemom gnol eno rof daeb eht denimaxe yehT
,htaerb rieht deniager d’yeht ecnO
,hguoroht eb ,nihteZ
,dedne gnos eht nehW
.resolc raugaj eht dellup sgel sih elihw
,sdoow eht otni htap eht no saw eh ,stnemom nI
.trofmoc rof htmraw hguone dedivorp taeh ydob s’elpuoc eht dna
?lesaew ,ytilaturb hcus fo gnits eht nessel emit seoD“
spetstoof s’raugaj ehT
.dnuorg eht ot delbmut eh sa elzzum sih depacse psag a dna
,snoitcennoc ynam htiw tnahcrem dwerhs a saw oetS ,yletanutroF
.smra sih dnuora sdnab etarobale lareves dna
,mih no kcab rieht denrut yehT
.sdog eht tneserper ot gnimialc
.rof deksa dah yeht daeb eht saw ti wenk eh tub – tnepres derehtaef a ti dellac dah hctiw eht
.mih htiw ekoj etavirp a gnirahs fi sa
.taorht sih morf emoc dah eciov s’hctiw eht
.setunim wef a flesmih thguob ylno d’eh wenk lesaew eht dna
.gnideelb regnol on erew sdnuow sih dezilaer noos eh tub
,romra rehtael krad ni raugaj a saw mih ot txen gnihcuorc tub
derumrum raugaj eht
ssefnoc neht dna
dlo na saw nisab eht dezilaer lesaew eht
.selcsum denifed-llew sih fo senil naelc eht gnirimda
.seilimaf elbon niargiT eht fo eno ot deit erew yeht demussa tsom tub
.ta gnikrow erew yeht elbat eht no ti decalp dna
”.niagrab eht edam uoY“
,sehtolc gninrub sih dna hteZ neewteb wons fo sehctap eht etipseD  .dias hctiw eht
”.decalper eb tonnac tI
”?rerecros a er’uoY“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,sdrazah rehto ro selbmarb dnuora klaw ot mih wolla ton did hctiw ehT
.der deniats erew stnirptoof sih
,skaep rieht hcaer noos dluow yeht
,erusaelp fo ezah eht hguorhT
.thgil eht ni demaelg
,edaf ot nageb sthgil eht
.seye s’lesaew eht otni yltcerid dekool uobirac eht
,daeb eht eveirter
”,egnarts leef yam ti tub ,truh t’now sihT“
.ecnahc eht evah reven dluow eh won dna
,noitceffa sih etipseD
.deb eht rednu kool ot seenk dna swap sih ot deppord neht
”.senob ruo ot dnuob osla si ti ,emos roF
”.won revo s’tI .kool t’noD
.noitseuq rehtona gniksa morf flesmih pots t’ndluoc tub ,lained rehtona ni
,thgit ton saw pirg siH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.meht htiw kaeps ot edisni flesmih decrof tub lla d’eh
roolf enots eht ssorca dekcalc sevooh erofeb dednammoc yeht
,skoob ni derevoc erew tsoM
.noitseuq erom eno deksa neht ,detatiseh hteZ
.pots ot sselrewop saw eh tub
,tfel dah iX retfA
.latrom a mrofsnart dluoc ecneirepxe eht taht wenk eh tub
revihs hteZ edam yehT
,truh tI .dnuorg eht ot dna
diarb rehtael eht ekat ot hguone gnol
.mih dnuora rehgih debmilc yeht sa
,naicisyhp a llac ot reffo s’oetS denilced dah hteZ
.deredisnoc lesaew ehT
.em ot tnatropmi yrev gnihtemos gnissim ma I“
.mih depacse niap fo naorg a nehw dezilaer ylno eh hcihw
.gniraehrevo oetS tuohtiw repsihw dluoc eh taht hguone esolc deppets neht
semalf nedlog eht sa etalitnevrepyh ot gninnigeb saw hteZ
”,ytic siht ni erusaert tsetaerg eht era uoY“
”?sdne retniw nehw gnivael eb uoy t’noW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,xof dna lesaew eht neewteb dereep eh sa dehsaba gnikool
,devlovni scitilop eht fo elttil wenk hteZ
,emac gnirps nehW
noitatuper a denrae ydaerla dah hcihw
.sehctiw yb delur ecno saw tanahoC“
”.taht tsurt ot uoy deen I
thgirtuo redrum ton did yeht esohT
.ssenhgiH ruoY ,esruoc fO“
,kcab pets ot flesmih delliw eh hguohtlA
meht ot txen dehcuorc eH
.elbat gnirobhgien a morf diuqil ylio raelc a htiw dellif
,semit lareves dellor eH
,gnikconk tnetsisni sih ot rood eht denepo hctiw eht nehW
.daeh rieht fo kcab eht otno ti fo thgiew lluf eht gnimmals saw eh retal tnemom A
”.neppah taht ekam nac I
.erom saw ti taht nwod peed wenk I kniht I“
.tenalPruF morf elbaliava ,ygolohtna syadiloH eht ni
,revewoh ,ymene ym emoceb uoy dluohS
.gnikamevol rieht sa gniyfsitas sa ylraen erusaelp a mih thguorb
,rerecros eurt a ekiL
”?dne ot cigam eht rof yaw rehtona ereht sI“
.taht no gnikrow neeb ev’I“
.enobregnif s’rehtafdnarg ym ecno saw daeb tahT“
.meht neewteb noitcennoc a delaever
”,lipiX ecnirP“
.efas si daeb ehT“
.yawa gnikcab deunitnoc iX
,si ti erehw wonk uoy fI .esaelp ,hteZ“
?lla s’tahT“ .deknilb hteZ
.lufituaeb neeb syawla ev’uoY
.niargiT fo selbon eht htiw yrlavir gnol a dleh dliuG s’tnahcreM ehT
.mih evas ot gniyrt ylno saw ecnirp eht wenk eh fi neve
– dluoc yeht sa netfo sa gniteem nugeb dah yeht tub
.ecnamor gniteelf a saw siht taht wenk hteZ
.siht od ot evah t’nod uoy
,reilrae stnemom tsuj lufituaeb ,ruf siH .mih delcric
.stnemevom gnihsals-yllacitrev
,dias yeht ”,noom s’retniW fo thgil eht ni dekan dnats tsum uoY“
,lesaew eht hguorht tohs niap gnizinoga nA
,noitareneg a revo rof denodnaba saw dnal ehT
.level ti peek ot luferac eb ot dah eh os
,ydob s’lesaew eht revo daerps ot nageb htmraw A
elzzum daorb rieht ssorca tperc elims desaelp A
,tsirw a dekcilf yehT
deb s’hteZ sdrawot ylkciuq deppets eh ,daetsnI
.elttil a tsael tA
.roirraw taerg a ma I“
.srehto morf noitcetorp rof ylno fi
”.daeb eht eriuqer od nac I sgniht wef ehT
.s’hteZ no seye krad rieht desucof neht
.rewop lufgninaem kcal I“
,redluohs sih no llef thgiew A
,meht no saw iX litnu
,eunitnoc ot etatiseh ton did tub
.xamilc sih gnihcaer
.drow hcae ot rovalf citoxe na evag tnecca kciht a tub
,yawa tlom dluow taoc retniw sih
.evitaerc tsael eht fo eno gnieb ,redruM
,esrup sih ni daeb eht deruces lesaew eht
sdrow s’hctiw eht ni taerht deilpmi ehT
.cigam krad yb detpmet neeb evah sgnieb resiw raF
.dliug ruoy rof rodassabma na eb dluoc uoY
,terces pihsnoitaler rieht peek ot decrof neeb d’yeht ,sutats rieht ni ecnereffid eht ot euD  .elbativeni
tsif a dehcnelc yehT  ”—luow eH
.gninrael rof retnec a saw tI
.rebos noisserpxe
.lwob eht revo devaw sdnah ediw
.tnatsid emaceb ezag s’hctiw ehT
hcrot eht ot ytic eht tup doolb s’raugaj ruoy
.lleps eht wener ot thgil taht rednu dekan dnats yam uoy ,degamad si taoc eht fI
.dnal ngierof a ni ecnaillad tnasaelp emos tsuj naht erom
.dehgis yeht ,deificap mees t’ndid eh nehW
.teef sih ot kcab teg ot deirt dna
,retal mih thguorb xof eht aet regnig eht tpecca did eh tub
.tsal ti ekam ot yaw a dnif ot
dilef dettops eht erehw deb worran eht no ,revewoH
.slanimirc sehctiw edam yeht ,toor koot seimra rieht reverehw dna
,ecitnerppa s'tnahcrem a sA
,ryC rohtarB yb ”taoC retniW ehT“
.sdooW sitsaB eht ni peed
,deltsirb ruf sih tub
”…I .yrros os m’I ,iX“
ecalp evitisnes yreve tsniaga dils yehT
.kaeps regnol on dluoc hteZ dna
.evom dluow gnihton tub ,ssertsid fo ngis fo dnik yna evig ot ,evom ot
.mih derongi yehT
,nehctik a neewteb snoisivid edam smeti niatrec fo tnemecalp eht
.mih denioj noos ohw ,hteZ ot wap a tuo dleh dna
enihs hgih a ot dehsilop neeb dah tI
– stenibac dna ,sevlehs ,sriahc
.liat s’lesaew eht evoba ecalp evitisnes eht dnuof sregnif nwo sih elihw
”.ruf ruoy tniona won tsum I“
.desuora dna detailimuh htob
pohskrow dna ,aera gnittis
,nwod detfird seye sih ”–detcepsus I
.deregnil euh tnecsediri tniaf a
,raer s’lesaew eht tsniaga spih sih dekcor dna
”.noos nruter lliw oetS retsaM“
seye sih ,detatiseh raugaj ehT
.sllaw etinarg eht otni delttes dah llihc a dna retniw fo dne eht raen saw tI
.ti tpursid yam droccA eht tsniaga ymehpsalb taerg a os
”.uoy rof lufituaeb eb ot detnaw tsuj I
”.won mih dne lliw I ro ,evaeL .enim si eH“
,dednuor a saw deniamer tahW
”?taht ekil gnihtyna nees uoy evah ,nihteZ ,lleW“
,pot eht ot ylraen dellif dna
”.doolb ni nword mih ekam lliw I ro ,evaeL“
snmyh eht fo mih dednimer tI
”.ssap ot emoc reven dluohs taht dna ,sriaffa enivid fo raelc yatS
lesaew eht yaw a ni hteZ dedrager seye nedloG .doots neht
?rehtona eb siht dluoC
”?gnissim er’uoy ti si tahW
.iX htiw pohs eht hcraes ot gnidneterp sruoh lareves tneps hteZ