,edisni delbmarcs dna dnuora deppihw I
”!timmad ,stcnitsni ruoy thgiF“
.psag a ni dekcus ev’dluow I
.depoh dah I ekil seno eulb dna der gnihsalf on tub ,sthgil erom was I
.retaw eht fo deracs t’nsaw I ,elihw gnol
tuo ekam ot tniaf oot saw ti tub ,em dniheb eciov s’nosillA draeh I
.tlah neddus a ot detloj rac eht sa noisiv ym dedoolf selbbuB
,tnemom a rof desuap I
,eerf tac tnafni eht tog dna sparts reh didnu I
”.od yllaer I  .os epoh I“
em ta deknilb rac s’enilef eht fo sthgildaeh eht erofeb gnol t’nsaw ti dna
”niaR eht ni tsaeB ehT“
,ezah diuqil eht fo dir teg ot seye ym deknilb I  ”.ay tog I“
.rood eht demmals dna rac s’nosillA fo edisni deppets I erofeb
.seenk ym revo ylsselefil depard smra ym dna
.deneppah gnihton dna
.namuh eht ot revo reh gnidnah dna
.elttil a tsuj nwod em dewols tI
.taolfa htob su peek ot thgif ot dah I dna ,em nword ot detnaw tI
.dnopser t’ndid ehs tub leehw gnireets eht tsniaga gnignab seenk reh
,tsrif ta sevren saw ti thguoht I
retaw eht fo tuo teg ot dedeen I
.dlrow s’tsaeb eht otni delttes I sa selbbub ria dna tnemevom fo ohce gnilwoh ,tnatsid eht gniraeh
,cifirroh erew yehT
.eromyna erac t’ndid I
.em ot dehcatta yllacisyhp eb ot demees taht tac eht rof gniwap sdnah namuh ybburg sih
enecs tnedicca eht morf yawa evord ew sa dleihsdniw eht gnitlep yltneg niar eht raeh ot em rehtob neve t’ndid tI
.wodniw eht tsniaga ffo pans swalc reh fo eno was I nehw s’tahT
,enog erew pleh rof seirc reH
.thginot esle enoyna gnitnuh eb t’ndluow eh wenk I
.retaw fo stelpord ynit esoht ni gnitanoser eciov s’ykceB raeh regnol on dluoc I
.nword lla ew erofeb ,enahS ,no emoC
”?thgir ,taht wonk uoY
.wodniw emas eht hguorht debmilc dna
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.ereht t’nsaw taht negyxo teg ot deen gnimaercs s’ydob ym thgif ot gniyrt
.em ta kool ot gnitfihs yllanif erofeb smra reh ta nwod dekool ehS  ”.wonk I  .haeY“
,meht retfa tuo debmilc I dna
.semag oediv no yenom dna emit hcum oot yaw gnidneps elihw
,dilos gnihtemos tsniaga ydob ym tser ot gnitrofmoc tlef tI
,wodniw edis dekcarc eht drawot repeed devom I
,rood eht rof dnuora elbmuf ot dah I
swalc reh htiw ti ta gnippir
,erom ecno pu delioc dna resolc flesym dellup I
.nettik eht rof devom dna
,dehca gnihtyrevE
.elbisiv flesreh ekam ot nosillA rof detiaw I sa elbmurg derit a htiw derewsna I ”,enif m’I“
,kciht rieht ffo llihc eht peek ot deirt scidemarap eht sa
rood eht ta gniwalc dna tleb taes reh ta gnitib detrats ehS
,smra ym otni ylsselefil llef ehs dna
,tnemevap tew eht no nwod deppolf I
.gninosaer sih rof gnihcraes
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.gnilims ylbaborp saw ehS
,tuons ym htiw detoor dna
,desserdda eb ot dedeen yeht ekil tlef I tub
.sdnuow nepo dna doolb mraw eht htiw ni gnixim retaw lanac dloc eht leef dluoc I
.reh dloh ot enoemos dedeen dlihc eht dezilaer nosillA tsael ta dna ,meht derongi I
.taes rac reh otni depparts tac tnafni eht was I nehw s’taht dna
elcihev eht fo tuo maws I os
.selbbub ria fo tsrub a ni
,avliS coruD naeS yb
tuons ym gnizarg ylerab
.edisbus ot detrats dah
.gnihton--llits dna ,niaga deirt I
,em otni dekcus ehs sa
.niks thgil s’nosillA tsniaga tuo gnidnats skram walc der fo seires eht was I nehw deirrow tog I tub
”niaR eht ni tsaeB ehT“
.dewollof taht tnurg eht elfits ot yrt neve t’ndid I dna
;gniyd saw I ekil tlef I
,yltfos deilper nosillA
,erom ecno ecafrus eht ot detpure I
esolc ni dekcut sgel ym htiw rood edis regnessap eht tsniaga gninael
”?esoht ta kool a ekat scidemarap eht evah uoy diD“
.dehguoc ehs nehT   .esaelP
.enilef eht otni efil gnihtaerb deirt I sa nwo ym htiw eson dna htuom s’tac eht revoc ot em rof reisae ti gnikam
.retaw eht fo tuo nettik eht peek dluoc I os tsuj
.dluoc I sa drah sa
,serop ym otni dekaos tI
,skcor tnaig htiw retaw eht gnitlep saw enoemos ekil srae ym ni gnirednuht saw ruopnwod ehT
.eerf tes eb ot gniggeb
,avliS coruD naeS yb
.ecaf reh revo lla pird ot deunitnoc avilas s’tsaeb eht tub
rehtom eht fo tnorf ni gnihsalps
.trihs tew ydaerla ym no dednuop niar eht elihw
”,elttil a hcti tsuj yehT
detca I erofeb dnoces a ylno rof od ot tahw revo delttab dnim yM  .tsaf
.tey evael ot ydaer etiuq t’nsaw I tuB
.sgnul deniarts ydaerla reh fo pot eht ta gnimaercs saw nettik reh elihw
,noitom wols ni gnivom saw I ekil tlef I
,saw ecno ti tahw fo elkcirt erem a ot nwod saw tI
epahs krad eht otni depmub yllautneve I tub
,borht srae ym ekam ot gnitrats osla saw erusserp ehT
,erom ecno yks krad eht ta kcab dekool I
”.oga emit gnol a em morf nelots saw taht gnihtemoS
.rodo eht morf evitaler tnatsid a ylbaborp
,trihs tew ym fo dloh debbarg rehtom eht nehT
,emit dnoces eht ti dnif ot regnol em koot tI
.flac ym otni gud ssalg emos sa
.daeh reh gnibbob ylesnet saw ehs dna
.edih ym decreip dna sehtolc ym hguorht gud swalc
yldliw sfooh ym gnikcik
.rac eht fo edis tnorf eht morf weiv ym otni gnimoc yllautneve ,teiuq tpek ehS
.selkcahs reh fo eerf teg ot tpmetta na ni tuoba gnihsarht saw ehs dna
,elcihev eht fo edis eht no dednuop I sa neve
.dessap dah emit hcum woh derednow I dna
.ydob reh fo tuo tsaeb eht dekcah ehs sa
,retaw fo rewohs eht morf rehtom enilef eht dleihs ot deirt I
sgnul dereenigne yllaiceps ruo taht gnipoh
.em no eid t’nod esaelp tsuj-
sa deppop sbir reH  .snoisserpmoc eht trats ot ecalp reporp eht saw deveileb I tahw dnuof dna
dworc eht otni dekans ecilop eht erofeb em htiw tcatnoc eye gnikam ylfeirb
,eniws a saw scidemarap eht fo eno ees ot dalg saw I
”!eid annog er’uoy ro gnilggurts potS“
,kcilf srae ym edam tI
.eromyna ereht ni deppart saw ehs ekil leef t’ndid ti
ygolohtna eht ni derutaef yllanigiro
,taht ssecorp ot elihwa em koot tI
.erehwyna gniog t’nsaw ehs tsael tA
,devil trohs woh rettam on
:yojne esaelP  .oga sraey ynam
,seenk ym ot llef dna edisa namuh ylrub a dehsup I
.gnikam saw ti dnuos wen
.retaw eht ni gnilgnad ,ereht gnitaolf tsuj saw ydob reH
neris sti prihc ecnalubma eht dehctaw ehs sa yas ot detrats nosillA
,trid detoor ylhserf ekil ,yhtrae dna hcir saw tI
degamad ylivaeh oot saw rac eht fi erus t’nsaw I
,tnedicca eht ecnis emit tsrif eht rof dna
.mih tuoba gniklat saw I wenk tsaeb ehT
rehtegot sregnif ym depsalc I os ,leef ot tniaf oot saw ti ,ereht saw ti fI
”.thgin gnol a dah ev’uoY
yrots s’yadoT dna
elcihev eht dnuora depsalc ylmrif swaj sih dah tsaeb eht
.thgirla eb ot gniog erew yeht--doG knahT
.erom ecno elzzum reh otni gnihtaerb erofeb
.did ykceB ym ekil eid reh tel uoy t’nod
.tey tsuj og ot ydaer t’nsaw I
,retaw eht otni degnulp I  2 fo 2 traP ,avliS coruD naeS yb
,sdnoces wef a ylno retfa dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.em eltrats ot ton gniyrt erew ehs fi sa ylsuoituac gnidaert ,deksa nosillA
,revo nekat yletelpmoc dah reh fo trap lamina ehT
”,edisni llits s’rehtom ehT“  .hguone saw ti
.daehrevo yks dellif duolc
nrub ot gninnigeb saw gel ym tub ,em dnuora lla retaw eht gnitnit saw taht euh der gniworg ylidaets eht erongi ot deirt I
,sselnoitom ereht yal tsuj ehs tub ,niaga gnipmup elcsum eht teg ot gnitsurht
.ecafrus eht rof dekcik yllacitnarf dna wodniw nekorb eht tuo su dehsup I
,sdlroW tnereffiD
.pu kaeps ot dediced reve ehs erofeb gnol reh llems dluoc I ,niaga esuaceb
hctiwt ot detrats srae yM
.ssalg eht tuo hcnup ot deirt I sa daeh ym edisni dewolleb I
efil eht demialc taht tnedicni ralimis a rof sdnema ekam ot redro ni
tub pleh ot ni depmuj namuh rehtonA
.sduolc kciht eht otni gnidecer nageb eh sa lwem detartsurf a tuo tel tsaeb eht gniraeh
.ecnatsid eht ni elbmur gnilkcac a tuo gnittel ,taht ta dehgual
,em htiw gnidaelp eb ot demees seye reh tub ,taes rac nwod edispu reh ni digir saw ehS
.reh raeh ot elba neeb evah t’ndluow namuh a erehw tsomla
pots ot reh rof gnimaercs
.nettik eht gnidnefed pleh t’ndluoc I
.gninoitseuq rof edisa em dellup dna
?ytrihT  ?sdnoces neT
traeh ym naht erom gnihton tub
.dnuorg eht no reh dial yeht sa
.gninnur enigne eht htiw rac eht ni ydaerla saw nosillA
,emit erom eno tuo dekcik I
yffup erew skeehc reH
.ssalg nekorb eht fo deniamer tahw ta sevooh ym fo tniop eht gnimia
.evil ot setunim eerht tuoba dah ehS
,tnecs erecnis sih fo ffihw a tog I dna
.rewop yna pu dliub t’ndluoc I
-esaelP“  .did ykceB ekil
.deifirtep saw nettik ehT
,gnol a ni emit tsrif eht rof dnA
,ecnatsid eht ni gnilbmurg mih raeh dluoc I
.rethgil elttil a demees eciov reh ,niaga ekops nosillA nehW
,tsaf gnidaf saw ecafrus eht morf thgil elbaliava ynA
.cinap ot deunitnoc tsuj tac eht tub
.devom gnihton ,ti no dellup I nehw tub
.sedisni ym ta deppir dna denrub tI
-gnihtyna--gnihtemoS
devol eh eno eht fo
.seirots rorroh eht lla daer dah I
,ni detsub yllaitrap saw tI
,egnarts eht eciton ot gninnigeb won tsuj saw I dna
.lanac eht otni repeed rac eht gnillup enigne eht
.nwo reh no evom t’ndid ehs
.evag yllanif wodniw eht dna
.emoh teg I nehw me‘ naelc ll’I“
”.thginot sevil rieht tsuj naht erom devas I“
ria dedeen sgnul llams reh tub ,wonk t’nod I ,htaerb reh dloh ot deganam tnafni eht woH
ti htiw gel ym gnikat ,drawni delkcub tI
,ywodahs a ni gnihtyreve gnipparw
;rehto hcae dootsrednu ew
.hguone ton tub ,evag tI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.thgin eht otni ffo gnivird erofeb
.dekaos yletelpmoc llits saw em dnuora gnihtyreve fi neve
.thgif a tuohtiw reh llik mih tel ot gniog t’nsaw I
.eslup a rof dekcehc I  .gnihtoN
.reh gnisol saw I
rehtaew esnetni eht dna sraef sih emocrevo ot sah enahS woN
,edis reh no enilef eht deppit I
,ereht tuo er’uoy fi …doG ,esaelP
,dednuos evah thgim ti sa egnarts sA
.emit erom emos su yub dluoc
,nekorb eb ot dah swodniw eht fo emoS
.gniyd saw ehS  .dnuos on edam ehS
elcihev eht fo edis eht dnuora yaw ym tlef ylkciuq I sa tub
.evirra ot ecnalubma eht rof detiaw dna enilef eht otno dleh I sa wonk ot dedeen I lla s’taht dnA
retaw fo tsim enif a gniyarps
.mih ot noitnetta yna yap t’ndid I
.em dednuorrus taht snamuh eht fo seciov dekcinap eht revo ymmom reh rof gnimaercs
.efil saw ti tub ,hguoc gnilgrug ,lufniap A
.erac sih ni rehtom eht gnivael tuoba retteb tol elohw a leef em edam
,dab t’nerew yehT
,won rewop nwo reh rednu gniklaw saw ehS
.gnihton tnaem yeht ekil sraet ym desare dna ecaf ym nwod dedacsac niar eht tub ,niaga gniyrc saw I
.dnuora nrut t’ndluoc I dna
”niaR eht ni tsaeB ehT“
,ykrum dna krad saw tI
,em fo tnorf ni thgir luos reh gnitae saw tsaeb ehT
,nosirp latem eht edisni flesym dehsup I sa edolpxe ot gniog saw ydob ym thguoht I
”.uoy fo duorp eb dluow ykceB erus m’I“
.ereh tuo neve ,reh gninword saw eH
.tniartser ytefas reh fo eerf teg ot gniyrt yllacitnarf enilef eht ees ylerab dluoc I dna
.tnecs railimaf sih ksam t’ndluoc retawniar fo llems psirc eht neve taht hguone gnorts dna
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
yltnedifnoc tsaeb eht dlot I ”,peels ot oG“
.niaga efas leef ot gninnigeb yllautca saw I
.smra reh gnibbur ylsuorogiv saw ehs dezilaer I nehw s’tahT
.tfel setunim owt revo tsuj dah ehS
teef defooh ym dekcik dna
.gniliaw citnarf s’nettik eht mlac wohemos ot demees yeht dna
.sdnah doog ni eb d’ehs wenk I
,resolc dekcik I sa knab etercnoc eht ot delbmarcs serugif yrrulB
gninepo llams eht hguorht ydob enicrop ym gnillup
.rettal eht ot resolc saw ti em dlot tuons yhcti dna sgnul gnimaercs yM
,em raeh ot reh detnaw I ,wohemoS
.wodniw edis raer eht ot devom I os
slewot yvaeh ni depparw meht fo htob
,tuo dekcik I ,flesym ecarb ot elbanU
sredluohs ym ffo tsud eht gnihsurb erew I fi sa
,mlac eht otni deraeppasid dna
”?yako uoy erA  ?enahS“
.tsehc ym otni enilef eht gnillup erofeb thgirpu emarf ynit reh gnitsiwt
.rac eht rof dedaeh dna
,kcab sgel ym deknarc I os
.tnedicca elbirret a dessentiw rekrowoc sih dna eh
,tnemom feirb taht rof ylno saw ti fi neve dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.elttab thguof drah ,gnol a retfa
daor eht drawot reh yrrac meht gnipleh
,tuons ym fo tuo ylivaeh delahxe I
.won gnilggurts t’nsaw rehtom ehT
,ecnatsid eht ni sneris eht fo yballul gnihtoos eht draeh I nehw
.gnineve taht reilrae neeb dah ti rednuht fo raor gninefaed eht naht
.gnihtaerb sa yllarutan sa tuo emoc ot demees tsuj tI
,su rof dehcaer dna egde eht ot nwod emac nam A
.rac degrembus eht drawot kcab maws dna
.daeh ym hguorht tohs niap neddus A
.rehtom eht ni esnopser a reggirt dluow dlihc reh fo swolleb eht ebyam tsuj ,ebyam taht depoh I
.emoh og annaw tsuj I  .oN“
.hteet deggaj fo lluf htuom a ekil dekool hcihw
,trohs saw elzzum reH
tsaeb ehT  ”.swalc reh hctaW“
,krad eht ta pu dekool I sa
.hteet ym dettirg I sa retaw eht hguorht gnihsup
,reteiuq hcum nworg osla dah niar ehT
sgnul reh fo snoiger tsepeed eht morf tuo ruop retaw eht gnittel
dliuG ’sretirW yrruF eht fo rednuof eht saw eH
.dedeen I tahw tog I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.dilos demees llits gnihtyreve
.egnulp ot deunitnoc elcihev eht sa teknalb dloc
diuqil ykrum eht edisni kcab degnulp I erofeb wolla dluow niar eht sa ria hcum sa ni dekcus I
.retaw pu gnittips elihw sdrow derit eht tuo ekohc ot gniganam wohemos ,dias I ”,ybab ,yako s’tI“
.larutan emac tahw did ylno tnafni ehT
smaercs gninedaed
sselnoitom dna yvaeh saw ydob reH
.og reh tel t’ndluow eH
.reh ot teg dluoc eh os tsuj yawa em edore dna
.flesym ot eton a edam I  .deraeppasid dna
.emit fo tuo gninnur saw ehS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
niks ym ffo leep ot gniyrt erew retaw eht fi sa
niaga tsehc s’rehtom eht no gnihsup detrats dna pu kcab tas I
.did tsuj uoy gniht evarb ylbidercni na saw tahT“
,seye sih otni derats I sa eruces dna esolc reh gnidloh pleh t’ndluoc I
,llits tub ,tac eht otni kcab efil erom tsurht ot deunitnoc I
tleb taes reh dekoohnu I
.esle gnihtyna naht ekas s’nettik eht rof erom
kcab ym no ylraen saw I
.rednu kcab em hsup ot deirt niar ehT
.niaga ehtaerb dluoc ehs dezilaer ehs nehw
.hguoc dna ekohc ot deunitnoc ehs sa
.thgin yniar dloc
.ecnalubma eht otni rethguad dna rehtom eht dedaol ylluferac eh sa enecs eht fo lortnoc ekat eniws wollef ym gnihctaw
,og tel t’ndluow ehS
nettik eht fo seirc deifirret eht yb decnelis noos saw ti tub
reh sa epacse ot deganam sgnul ym ni tfel dah I ria revetahW
.edaf ot nageb enilanerda eht sa ydob ym gnikcohs dna swalc reh htiw repeed ni gniggid
,llab gnilwob a ekil gniknis saw tI
.ees ot drah saw ti tub
.rac eht otni tuons ym gnignab ylraen erofeb
netsil dluow reveohw ro ,doG ot deggeb I
,lwoy ot detrats nettik ehT
.won neve ,nerdlihc orhtna ot gniod erew snamuh sgniht eht wenk I
.kcab gnihtemos koot osla I“  .ruf dehcnerd
,traeh reh trats ot detpmetta I
,dehgual ylraen I
ygolohtnA sdrawA ltoyoC eht ni derutaef seirots dah osla eH .snikS tnereffiD
,elbissop erew ti fI
.gnihtyreve fo kcart tsol I dna tnemom a rof dednilb saw I
.retaw lanac eht otni gniroloc doof dexim dah enoemos ekil euh der tniaf a htiw pu gniduolc
pu desnet dna pil mottob ym tib I
,yaw rehtie tub ,dezilauqe t’ndah tsuj erusserp eht fi ro
”.elpoep owt devas uoY
niar eht tsael tA
,nettik eht dnuora mra eno htiW
,dnah ni esolc rethguad reh htiw
.hctiwt ot detrats tuons sih
.rac s’nosillA ot kcab yaw ym dereggats I ,em htiw enod erew ecilop eht nehW
.gnihtyna od t’ndid ehs tub ,ria rof gnipsag
lanac eht morf enilef eht gnillup ni namuh rehtona dedia nosillA
.evil ot gniog erew yeht esuaceb ,hguoht erac t’ndid I
.egde eht rof miws dluoc I os sgniraeb ym teg ot gniyrt
.ydaerla setunim eerht ot esolc neeb evah ot dah tI
,rood edis regnessap eht denepo dna pu doots yllanif I nehw dna
”?tuo dekcehc teg ot tnaw t’nod uoy erus uoy erA“
.egde eht rof delddap I sa
,devaeh tsehc reH
,noitcerid ym ni pu dekool eH
”!esaelp--niaga toN  .niaga em ot siht od uoy t’nod-
pley sselmrah a ekil erom demees eciov sih fo ohce eht tub
;dewollaws I semit ynam woh wonk t’nod I
.drah dna peed efil ni dekcus dna ecafrus eht ot tohs I nehw laeuqs deifirroh a sa tuo emac psag ehT
;eldnah eht revo dnah nevolc ym gnipsalc yllautneve
.hguoht rettam t’ndid tI
hteet ym dettirg I sa tnemom a rof deraeppasid niap ehT
.em tel t’ndluow ti dna
.muucav a emoceb dah ydob ym fi sa
,yarp ot detrats I os ,tnemom taht ta stcnitsni nwo ym thgif ot dah I
.edisni em tel ot gniog t’nsaw eh dna
ydob rednet ym morf yawa nettik eht gniyrp erofeb detuohs I
.pots ot em rof gnidaelp saw ydob ym hguoht neve
.levarg toh htiw dellif gnieb erew yeht fi sa tlef sgnul ym dna
,mrots gnigar a otni tuo derutnev enahS retfa ,emit tsaL
seippup suoremun dna rentrap sih htiw saxeT ni sevil yltnerruc dna
,seye s’gip eht otni gniees tsuJ
.rac eht ni teg s’tel nehT“  ”.derit m’I
.srettam pleh t’ndid sthgil gnilppir eht drawot gnimmiws saw I taht tcaf eht dna
,tac deracs eht elttab ot tnaw t’ndid I
.stsrub trohs ni niar gnirednuht eht tuo delecnac taht
.niaga ti did I os
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,elcihev eht drawot maws I
,enilef eht ot gnidnet nageb eh sa dehctaw I
.4 emuloV raoR dna
enim tem ezag dekcinap s’namuh eht nehw tuB
,gniod nwo reh fo ton
”,ereht tuo deneppah revetahw ,lleW“
.deracs saw ehs esuaceb ti did ylno ehS“
,erom elttil a nekrad ot nageb rac eht fo edisni eht dna ;rehtona nahT
.reh evas dna yrt ot gniog saw I fi