.yug wen eht no yalp ot knarp etarobale
,eruliaf eht fo emit eht ta deipucconu erew yeht dna
,riaper a neewteb etaitnereffid ot denrael dah eH
.ti ot txen nwod yal ot flesmih derevuenam neht
.moor eht deretne feihC eht nehw nepo rood eht draeh ton dah eh taht thguoht ni tsol os
,yaler eht def taht langis eht decart dna scitamehcs eht hguorht degap eh ,dap atad sih tuo gnilluP
",em tsuj saw ti thguoht I
,ecnalg syawedis a geR evag nooccar ehT
geR dna feihC  .deksa ehs
.ediw werg seye s'dorlE
.sdnoces ytriht ni nigeb lliw noitarotser ytivarg laicifitrA"
,eerhT yaB ograC ,evitisop erehpsomta eht edisni saw eh
",ereh revo eb dluohs siht wonk uoY"
,dorlE dias ",srab nietorp ekil uoy epoh I"
",dnif thgim eh tahW
.tiurf emos otni gnitib elihw terref eht dias
.rewohs eht ni elihw sehtolc sih no eye eno peek ot denrael dah eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.elkcuhc tibbar eht edam hcihw
.ecnaL ,sknahT"  .IA eht dias
.seludom eht fo eno enimaxe ot nwod tlenk feihC
.eulb eno dna kcalb eno
setag cigol esohT"
"?eriter I retfa litnu tiaw siht naC"
,niaga delcyc syaler ehT
,llaw eht edisni stoob sih ot pu yllatnoziroh yal terref ehT
.ylreporp seriw eht detcennocer eh sa daeh sih ekahs ot nageb dorlE
dias "!doog ,hO"  .ecnaL deilper
,seriw owt erew daehklub eht tsniaga llaw kcab eht ot dehcattA
".detavitca ylluf si metsys eht litnu tuoba gnivom morf niarfer esaelp
.deneppah gnihton tub
.rood sti no sehctac eht gnisaeler nageb dna
dorlE no denwad ylwols s'tI
,nokraD ahsarheT yb
.kced eht ot ti gnippord erofeb
,lleW"  .redneH dias
,tuohs delffum a emac
,lla ti fo retnec eht ta tas flow gnuoy ehT
,denaomeb eh ",on hO"
,detroper seirujni oN
.ecaf eht ni mih gnirats si ti ereht tey ,elbissop ton ylpmis si gniees si eh tahw taht mih gnillet si
.nwod tas dna niatpaC eht etisoppo riahc a dekcip eh
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.dap atad sih no smeti riaper fo tsil sih dekcehc dna
.puos s'thginot rof hcum oS" ,degnirc feihC
---  .der lenap eht no syaler detalernu yletelpmoc ,tnereffid owt tfel tub
",feihC ,kcab thgir eB"
.og tel yllanif yeht ,sgnidnal dna sffoekat ynam woh swonk ohw retfa dna
.erehwesle raeppa ot smotpmys detalernu wen desuac ylno
.tcerrocni saw langis eht erehw dnuof eh litnu setag cigol eht hguoht kcab yaw sih gnikrow
,niaga eciov lamron sih ni flow eht deunitnoc
sihT' .lenap eht ta kcab neht
.kcuts saw ti fi ees ot ti no deppat dorlE
,laerec yrd emos no gnihcnum yellag eht ni feihC eht dnuof geR
pirg mrif a tpek dnah eerf sih elihw ,ecalp ni flesmih rohcna ot elba saw eh
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.gnitcaer era setag cigol eseht yaw eht ,ni sA"
,kcis si taht pihs eht s'ti tuB
.htuom sih otni serehps eht fo eno deppop eh sa
.sllaw dna ,gniliec ,roolf eht no tfel snrettap puos tcartsba eht gnirimda elihw
,tibbar eht deilper "?he ,llew tahT"
.niatpaC emaceb eh erofeb ,reenigne feihC eht saw eh nehw kcab ,geR ot gnoleb sgalf eulb ehT"
seludom laudividni rieht
",esruc sreenigne ehT"
.ksat eht dehsilpmocca hcihw loot yna saw 'boj eht rof loot thgir eht'
"?uoy htiw gnisseM"  .dorlE deksa
',esnes on sekam
".gnilpuoc eht fo tuo thgir seriw eht deppiR
,sgal eht euqrot t'ndid ylbaborp stoidI"
,noitarugifnoc dehctamsim lanigiro rieht ot kcab seriw owt eht gninruteR
.eciov s'IA eht deilper "?ngisnE ,seY"
".ylreporp ti riaper ot stpmetta elpitlum dootshtiw sah hcihw kcah A
,koob eht yb ti gniod si eh sa hcum sa ni ,llew gniod si eH"
",era uoy nehw ydaeR  .ecnaL ,yakO"
maercs ot deunitnoc mrala ehT
.ecaf a gnikam dna daeh sih gnikahs flow eht dias ",pu taht naelc ot evah t'nod I dalG
yab eht fo tnorf eht ta lenap evissam a dehcaorppa feihC eht ,eikooc tsal eht gnitae retfA
,syaler rehto owt was eh litnu
",seog gnihtyreve erehw wonk I"
".did yltnerappa I hcihW
.ta gnikool saw eh tahw erus yleritne ton llits ,lenap desopxe eht erofeb doots dorlE
.nwo sti fo nerdlihc evah ot hguone dlo won si moor tahc CRI s’ohw
"?geR dna em htiw reeb a erahs dna yellag eht ot nwod emoC  ?kaerb a ekat uoy t'nod yhW"
,pu tas sreenigne htob
,toof s'feihC eht ta dellup yltneg flow eht dna
,demrifnoc eh ",ris ,seY"
,yletaidemmi degagne sevlav ytefas ehT"
,lenap eht otni denael eh gniggurhS
".yab ograc eht ot denifnoc gniht detsalb eht peeK" ,geR dedda
,elbac rewop tsal eht detcennocsid feihC
.wolley fo aes eht nihtiw neddih
woh dna ,noitautis eht gninialpxe snrut koot
,niaga scitamehcs eht ta dekool dorlE
.htlaeh sih dna ssergorp sih kcehc ot
.trop ssecca eht fo sllaw eht nwod mih gniparcs tuohtiw
",eb ot desoppus er'yeht tsael ta rO  !seikooC"
.yab ograc eht hguorht ylsuonimo deohce taht naorg cillatem
.eugitaf htiw degnit won ,eciov yreehc lausu sih ni dorlE deilper ",enif ,eniF"
lenap a fo pil eht rednu degdew toob sih fo eot eht htiW
.moortser eht drawot rodirroc eht nwod dednuop eh sa dias eh
"?kcis pihs eht si woH"
.rorre na gnitacidni ,der saw yaler enO  .eno tpecxE
"?em htiw gnissem tsuj syug eht dna uoy erA"
,seludom eht fo lareves neewteb roolf eht no nward neeb dah senil klahC
.rof detnuocca erew sloot sih fo lla taht deifirev dna xob loot sih denepoer eh ,tuo ecnO
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.gniliec ot roolf morf dehcterts sgalf wolley fo llaw a woN
emos lla saw siht taht dna
devomer neeb dah epat wolley fo spirts lareveS
.rodirroc ytpme eht ot feihC eht deksa
,pots sti dehcaer ti litnu llaw eht morf tuo ti dellup dna
"?eno etirw dluoc uoy ebyaM"  .feihC eht dias
.ffo tnew noxalk gninraw noisserpmoced eht dna
.ecalp rieht nekat dah sgalf neerg ,erom ton fi ,ynam sa tsuj tub
.tnemeerga ni deddon ohw
".esruc eht sah eH"
,yad driht eht nO  ---  .dehsinav neht
,yab ograc eht tfel ti sa ria fo hsur evisolpxe eht gnitiawa
.rorre eht gniyalpsid yaler eno eht no desucof eh
,deltrats flow ehT
.elbat eht ot txen gnidnats ,ecnetsixe otni derekcilf egami s'ecnaL  ".gnuoy s'eh dna
.taht tuoba ekoj neve t'noD"
,doog hO"  .feihC dias
.yllamron gnitarepo erew skcar fo riap eht no syaler eht fo llA
,tuhs seye sih dehcnip ylevitcnitsni dorlE
.feihC eht ecaf ot gninrut ecno reven
dorlE dna feihC ehT
.nirg a htiw geR detseggus
.sdnah sih fo ffo sbmurc gnitsud ,flow eht deksa
.epat sih htiw ti no 'X' wolley egral a gnicalp
.eramthgin gnivil a ta gnikool era uoY"
.ruof rebmun s'tahT"
.roolf eht morf pu flesmih dekcip ylsuoituac eh sa ,feihC eht deksa
,noitatneirosid ecuder oT
.esle erehwemos rorre rehtona desuac ylpmis metsys eht ot riaper yreve
,rehto hcae ta dekool htob feihC dna geR
.yaw suoivbo yna ni detcennoc ton erew taht smetsys ssorca semitemoS
.egnahc on ni detluser
.won thgir ssenlli na hcus gnitaert yltnerruc si etam s’reenigne eht
srood erusserp eht ot selbac rewop eht was dna ,eye eno
sdrawkcab reggats mih gnikam
",tuo em llup ,yakO"
”esruC sreenignE ehT“   yojne esaelP
.egdirb eht morf deef oidua eht detcennocsid eh sa
ffo tuc yltpurba saw rethgual s'geR fo dnuos ehT
.yab ograc eht fo tuo yaw sih dekcab feihC ehT
.deirrow ylthgils gnidnuos ,flow eht deksa
noitidnoc rorre emas eht gniwohs llits syaler ehT
.elkna s'feihC eht no
,delbmessasid yletelpmoc neeb dah stellap ehT
.kcah a dna ,hctap a
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.setunim fo rettam a ni ffo raew dluohs taht tub
.ylsuoires yrev dias eh ",ti ta evaH"
"?siht mih gniwohs eb ot gnuoy elttil a eh
.mih deteerg tahw rof deraperp ton saw eH
lenap eht otni kcab ti demia neht ,maeb niht licnep raen a ot
.mih erofeb tuo dial scitamehcs gniriw eht htiw
enot krad a ni feihC deilper
.won sah dik eht tahw s'tahT" ,deddon geR
",raf os ,sreenigne ruof depmuts evah taht setag cigol ,seY"
.ylknalb derats tsuj feihC ehT
?esle gnihtemos ot egnahc ylneddus smotpmys eht evah ot ylno ,ssenlli na rof tneitap a detaert reve uoy evaH"
".lenap eritne eht gnideef rewop eht si elggot nac I gniht ylno eht
,feihC eht ot kool emas eht denrut neht
seno egnaro elpuoc a dna sgalf eulb lareves tuo detniop eh sa feihC deilper
,taht detcepxe dah eH
.detcepxe sa tsuj
dereves neeb dah hcaE
.redneH dna geR dnuof eh erehw ,yellag eht ot yaw sih edam dna
.niatpaC eht dias ".sraey
"?srood erusserp eht elbasid uoy did yhW"
,htaerb peed a koot
stellap eht fo eno dekcolnu feihC
,ti evoba detacol ettelap eht rof emas eht did neht eH
.tif gnihguoc a otni devloved neht ,wollaws ot hguone flesmih lortnoc ot deganam tsuj ylno dna
".ecalp eht naelc maets dna emoh teg ew litnu puos detnemref ekil llems lliw pihs elohw ehT"
thgil sti deworran dna
.meht tfel dah feihC eht erehw dnuorg eht no gniyal
".strats melborp eht erehw si tahT"  .feihC dias
.terref desufnoc eht deksa "?esoht era tahW"
latnoziroh fo kcats a saw rood eht dniheB
.deddon egami s’ecnaL
---  .yab ograc eht tfel neht
".ecnaL ksa tsuJ
",rehto hcae wonk ot teg nac uoy os ,emit enola emos evah uoy fo owt eht tel tsuj ll'I"
.ecalp fo tuo erew lenap eht fo kcab eht ta deirub seriw owt eht ylnO
denrae evah lliw uoy
".draob no emac reve I erofeb gnol ecalp ni tup erew llA
.rodirroc eht fo edis etisoppo eht no ylralimis did dorlE
.flow gnilims eht dias
,tnemtaert eht egnahc uoy emit hcaE
denepo ylwols eh sa
,detrats uoy erofeb naht sehctap rewef htiw siht fo tuo emoc uoy fI
.srood erusserp niam eht no srotom eht gnilbasid ylluferac
.desufnoc ylrettu
taht denrael dah eH  .dlrow laer eht ni dekrow yllautca metsys a woh no gniraeb yna dah ylerar launam ngised eht ni nettirw saw tahw taht denrael dah eH
.teg uoy raf woh eeS"
.lenap eht ot denruter dna gnidloh saw eh htaerb eht desaeler eh feiler htiW
.sdrow raews fo yralubacov wen yleritne na denrael osla dah eh
tahW'  .neerg gniyalpsid syaler eht fo lla ni detluser
",flesruoy no siht thguorb uoy ,feihC yrroS"
.troffe eht htiw gninaorg
.feiler htiw flow eht
,tuo dellup eb ot meht dewolla hcihw sliar gnipocselet no hcae
.deppots dah gnihguoc sih ecno
.feihC ,daeha og uoY"
daeh sih koohs eh desolc rood eht ecnO
,roolf eht raen noitisop efas a emussa esaelP
,daed tnew slenap eht no syaler eht fo lareves ,trapa meht dellup dna
,doof fo yart a flesmih gnibbarg retfA
---  .terref eht delbmurg ",wonk I ,wonk I"  .IA eht dias
",delaes dna desolc si rood eht taht metsys eht sllet hctiws tahT
",ti tog yletinifed s'eH"
,mih erofeb kcar eht debbarg dna
,der denrut yletaidemmi lenap eht ni syaler eht fo flaH
,ylluferac mih evomer ot gniyrt
.flow eht thguoht '?slleh eht
.suoludercni gnikool dorlE dias
,nirg a htiw dias eh
.kcen reh dnuora gniraew saw cidem eht taht noci suoigiler eht ot detniop niatpaC eht neht
yllaudarg neht ,roolf eht otno elttes seidob rieht tlef
.gnittis neeb dah stellap eht erehw
.terref eht deilper
deksa "?esruc neesnu na ot siht etubirtta uoy dnA"  ".gnineddam s'tI
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
dorlE woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.meht fo hcae neewteb gninnur seriw repmuj htiw roolf eht no tuo dial
",daerps ti tel t'nod dnA"
"?tfel si taht lla taht sI"
,niatpac eht drawot erutseg enecsbo na detcerid feihC ehT
.egdirb eht morf eciov s'geR emac
.noitidnoc der a detacidni ro
.taht etorw ohw swonk ydoboN
,égétorp sih no ni kool ot dediced feihC
dnah eno ni xobloot a htiw yawllah eht otni gnitaolf
.gniwehc elihw dias eh
",taht ekil tneserp snoitidnoc enummiotua emos tub ,esac a hcus detaert yllanosrep reven evah I"  .geR deksa
.etag cigol tnereffid yleritne na ot del
,tcud ria na fo gnitarg eht ni kcuts sregnif sih dna
.mih etaderp seno egnaro ehT
.dab taht eb t'nac ti ,no emoC"
.tekcos sti otni eno wen eht detresnier dna ,etag cigol decart ylwen eht tuo dellup flow eht ,gninworF
deliaf ytivarg eht nehw nevo eht ni neeb dah yeht taht denialpxe dna
feihC dias ",ereht nwod dab eb tsum tI"
,deganam yllanif geR  "!esruC s'reenignE ehT"
",pihs eht hguorht rehtruf yna daerps ssem taht tel I erofeb decalper yab ograc eritne eht evah ll'I
,hcrot sih tuo dellup feihC
,noitarugifnoc lanigiro sti ot kcab metsys eht sgnirb riaper ruoy sselnu sgalf sreenigne rehtona evomer tonnac uoY  .wal s'reenignE"
.sehctap fo pot no ,sehctap fo pot no ,sehctaP
.daeherof reh gnibbur saw redneH
",setag cigol fo yarra na tsuj s'tI
tellap rehto eht no saw hcihw fo eno
depparwnu eh nehW
,dnuof neeb ton dah
.epat etihw htiw deggalf dna depparw neht
.reenigne feihC sih etisoppo taes a gnikat
"?seriw dessorc owT"  .feihC eht dias
”esruC sreenignE ehT“
",tsixe ton seod ,siht srevoc taht koob ehT"
.esruc lacixodarap siht fo pihs eht sdir
.sraey 04 tsael ta rof neeb sah dna
,esruc eht teg t'nac selaM"  .deddon ylno ohw
.sriaper fo sraey ytrof revo ta gnikool saw eh taht
,eulb ot kcalb dna
.raeppa ot srorre esuac dluow srood niam eht no hctiws ytefas eht gnitcennocsid taht esnes edam ti
.seriw owt tsrif eht detcennocsid dah eh nehw sa
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     "?uoy oD"
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.ylnmelos feihC eht detouq
.meht fo ynam ot txen seton delbbircs htiw
,geR deksa "?seog woH"
".ehcadaeh a em gnivig si siht dna ,reenigne na neve ton m'I"
",em tsuj toN"  .flow eht dias
rorre wen siht morf langis eht kcab gnicarT
seriw dehctamsim eht fo eno
,neris eht decnelis tekcos eht otni kcab etag cigol lanigiro eht gnittuP
.erom oN  .enod s'ti
"?esnesnon suoititsrepus fo dnik taht ni eveileb yllaer uoy oD"  .redneH
thguat neeb sah eh gnihtyrevE
,noitrexe fo tnurg a htiW
.niaga neerg lla erew yeht litnu spets lacigol rieht hguorht gnilcyc meht fo llA
",tniop gnitrats eht si taht tuB
,elbat eht ssorca knird sih deyarps ylraen geR
,xobloot sih fo ecafrus eht ot kcuts dna
.niaga elbmurg ot nageb eh sa feihC eht dias ",trop ot kcab teg ew nehw riaper reporp a deen lliw tI  .hctaP"
.yrruFoS no dnuof eb nac yrots siht ni sretcarahc eht dnuora ecalp gnikat seirots eroM
.feihC eht dias ",drah oot mih gnikrow ma I woh em gnillet redneH evah ot si tnaw I gniht tsal ehT
",ysub neeb evah uoY"
.yab ograc eht drawot yaw sih degdurt eh sa feihC denihw
,no tup gnieb saw eh kniht ot gninnigeb ,flow eht deksa
,niatpac eht dias ",esuba no gniredrob si siht ,feihC tuB"
emos gnimrofrep erew eh hguoht sa dekool tsomla tI
,roolf eht ot xobloot sih deruces feihC
,ti xif ot tpmetta hcae taht demrifnoc eb dluoc ti
"?ecnaL ,KO gnihtyreve sI"  .flow eht dias
.ti detpmetta reve eh taht tegrof I taht tseuqer sih si
,emas eht deniamer gnihtyreve dna ,riap rehto eht detcennocsid eh nehT
.ecnaL deilper ",feihC ,os diarfA"
.lacitrev ylraen saw ti llit drawnwod tovip ot ti dewolla neht
.niaga meht detcennocer dna seriw eulb owt eht detcennocsid eh nehT
",puos gnitaolf yb detanimatnoc ton gniht ylno eht erew yeht ,nevo eht ni erew yeht ecnis dnA"
,flesmih htiw desaelp ,delims flow ehT
.yaler rewop a pu kcip ot dehcaer eh sa nageb eh
",t'nac uoy yllautcA"
.yawa saw eh elihw gniod neeb dah feihC eht tahw denimaxe flow ehT
yab ograc eht ni srekaeps eht morf pop llams a saw erehT
meht ot txen daehklub eht no srettel yvaeh egral ni deklahC
.yab ograc ytpme eht gnisserdda
",no kcab ti nrut yeht nehw regnorts leef syawla tI"
".elihw a rof teg ew lla eb thgim yehT"
",'egamad' on saw ereht os
,feihC demialcxe ",sdog hO"
.'TNOD'  .drow elgnis a saw
,feihC eht htiw gnikrow elihw taht
.geR deksa "?dnA"
.der deniamer eno emas eht tub
.hteet sih ni dleh thgilhsalf eht htiw
,xob loot s'feihC eht morf eno wen a htiw ti decalper dna ,etag cigol eht devomer eh nehW
,yad eno neeb ylno s'ti lleW"
kcalb ot eulb ,rehto eht ot dehcattaer dna
.loohcs lacinhcet fo sraey evif ni deniag dah eh naht egdelwonk lacitcarp erom denrael ydaerla dah dna shtnom eerht rof etam s'reenigne na neeb ylno dah dorlE   2 fo 1 traP ,nokraD ahsarheT yb
,nokraD ahsarheT yb ”esruC sreenignE ehT“
t'nsI"  .evil tnew yeht sa
.xodarap lacigol yb no thguorb ehcadaeh A
,sgalf deroloc eht ot gnitniop ,dorlE deksa "?ruoF"  .feihC dias
.der pu gnimoc yaler tnereffid yletelpmoc a ni detluser lanigiro eht gnitresnier dna etag cigol wen eht tuo gnilluP  .der won erew
htiw derevoc saw lenap desopxe ehT
I'  .thguoht taht ta delims feihC ehT
.pihs eht tuohguorht gnar eciov tnasaelp s'IA ehT  .feihC dias
.efil ot kcab emac syaler eht ,eulb ot eulb detcennoc eh nehW
.epat neerg fo llor a flow eht gnidnah elihw ,dehsinif eh ",siht
,kcalb ot kcalb ,riap tsrif ehT
,yab eht edistuo mih sdael htap eht fI  .gnikoj ton m'I"  ".taht
",peels dna doof laminim tsael ta steg eh erus ekam dna mih no eye na peek lliw I"
,degreme terref ehT
.IA eht deilper ",lla ta ton ,oN"
"?raeppa smotpmys tnereffid
gninrom txen ehT
.ylreporp boj rieht od t'ndluoc ohw swerc dnuorg tuoba gnilbmurg
,flow regnuoy eht ot feihC dias ",ereht ni dniheb gnihtyna evael ot tnaw t'noD"
".eerht s'tahT  .egnaro dna ,geR ,uoY"
.rehto eht ni epat wolley fo llor egral a dna
,feihC eht dnuof dorlE nehW
,gninialpxe dehsinif yeht emit eht yB
.epat wolley fo spirts gnirettulf elttil
rorre lanigiro eht fo ecruos eht elihW
.yltalf redneH detats ",deppiuqe t'nera yeht
niaga delcyc syaler eht fo lla
,settelap ediw retem
.ereht tuo s'tahw wonk ot sah eH"
.flow eht dias ",kcab meht paws tsuJ  ?ti s'tahT"
flesmih ot delims feihC
.esruc siht fo pihs eht dir ot
.kcab yaw eht no yellag eht tsap gnuws I"
.niaga tiucric eht decarter yllatnem eh sa ,thguoht eh
.ti xif ot detpmetta I retfa keew a rof peels t'ndluoc I"
,feihC eht deltrats ti taht evissergga os eciov a ni dorlE delrans "!GNIHTON HCUOT"
.degdolsid emoceb evah yam hcihw stcejbo gnillaf rof hctaw dna
"?ti si tahW"  ".siht fo esuaceB"
,lortnoc yeht tahw fo hcum rotinom nac I elihW
,niaga seriw eht gnitcerroC
.xobloot sih flow eht dednah feihC ehT
.metsys detalosi na era
"?steliot eht tuoba tahW"  ".puos
"?knarp a sa yletomer detcejni gnieb srorre eseht erA
.dekcol ti llit drawpu segnih sti gnidlof emit siht hguoht
"?yaw tahw nI" .ecnaL deksa
.denettalf srae sih nehT
.IA eht dias ",ssem etulosba na si yellag eht tub
,siht fo esuaceb saw tI
,flow eht deksa "?ecnaL"
",srieht setagen riaper ruoy ro
.draoba nettog evah thgim esaesid emos taht deirrow ,redneH deksa "?tahw tog s'ohW"
.dessecca eb dluoc meht no sevlav dna syaler fo syarra eht os
.scitamehcs eht ta gnirats llits elihw flow eht dias ",siht tog tsomla ev'I kniht I
.ssa sih no llaf dna
,lli ylbadnatsrednu si niatpac ehT"
.dne raf eht ta hctiws elgnis a ot tcennoc dna yab ograc siht fo htgnel eht nur yehT
,noitartsurf ni esicrexe na emaceb ylkciuq dna ,ytlevon sti tsol noos ytivarg orez ni sriaper gnikam taht denrael osla dah eH
.duola terref eht deksa "?ti seog woH"
.rettab detsaot fo sllab elttil sa tuo emoc dah dna
.meht tfel dah eh erehw niamer ot desufer strap dna sloot nehw
.seriw dessorc owt ,seY"
.roolf eht no gniyal selbac detcennocsid egral eht ot gnirutseg ,deksa eh
.slevel lamron ot pu thguorb ylwols saw ytivarg eht sa
.htuom sih otni stcejbo lacirehps llams gniffuts mih dnuof eh ,flow eht ot denrut eh nehW
,geR dna lenap siht rof elif no evah I drocer ylno ehT"  .ecnaL detcejni
peed a htiw nepo gnuws dna dehctalnu rood eht sa
.rerutcafunam eht neeb neve evah thgim tI
,metsys eht no msicroxe ro ,etir enacra
reivaeh dna reivaeh emoceb
,geR dias ",etam s'reenigne wen ehT  .flow eht ,dorlE"
".pu dne lliw taht erehw wonk lla ew tub
,'raelc lla' eht delangis ecnaL nehW
feihC eht ot elpuoc a dessot eH
,trop eht gnirevoc lenap eht deruces dna desolc neht terref ehT
.dorlE deksa "?hctap ro kcaH"
.neerg detacidni won rorre suoiverp eht dna
,redneH ta dekool tsuj feihC ehT
,ffo ti dekcol dna deppac neht
.suoludercni dekool nooccar ehT
.flesmih ot dias eh ,'taht deirt evah dluohs
.niatpaC eht dias