.stimil sti dnoyeb ydob reh ecrof ot yruf suoethgir reh degarevel aetnaP ,lamina laref a ekil gnilranS
,esaelP“  .delrans drapoel eht
.sdog dlo eht fo tnavres a ,demhsaH suoiretsym eht deretnuocne yeht erehw
!rewsna ot uoy dnammoc I
trats lliw shtaed ruoy tub
ydob ’siragaS reh fo htmraw ekilnus eht ,elggurts eht dimA
er’uoY“  ”?yeht t’nera ,rof era sekats eseht tahw s’tahT“
”.regnad ni llits s’ehs fi wonk ot deen I .aetnaP llik ot deirt eH“
.redluohs ’siragaS reh sserac yletanoitceffa ot drawrof dehcaer aetnaP
.drabbacs eht rof detnuh lacarac eht sa daerd fo esnes gnimlehwrevo tsomla reh ekips ot devres ylno ti ,won thgiR .saera etamitni
”kraM s’partaS ehT“
.ymmud gniniart a ekil mih ta gnikcah yleuqsurb nageb dna kcab s’xnyl eht fo pot no tpael ehS
.evisneffo eht no tnew nirihS
.atihanA aruS ivdrA fo
ereh deripsnart tahw ot detaler si ti spahreP
.despalloc dna llaw etisoppo eht dehcaer eh ,stnemom wef a naht erom rof dnats ot yraew ooT
”kraM s’partaS ehT“   yojne esaelP
sreh tem spil s’aetnaP ,erom ecno dna
,moor eht fo edis etisoppo eht ot delwarc demhsaH ,gnitrons dna seye sih gnilloR
.swolleb a fo gnipmup eht ekil gnillaf dna gnisir tsehc
,roolf enots drah eht tsniaga aetnaP hsams ot drawkcab gnippolF
”,ytud ym gniod ylno saw I“
sevlac s’aetnaP ssorca dellor retaw looC
.klats taehw a fo htdiw eht yb elzzum sih gnissim
sdog dlo eht fo eno fo eniltuo eht gnizingocer
”.htiw regnad eht ecaf rehtar d’I eno on s’erehT“
.luficrem si partaS ehT“
roolf eht ssorca gnirettiks ,hself gnihsarht reh fo tuo dils reggad ehT
”!taht evivrus ot desoppus t’nerew uoy…uoY“
.selzzum rieht fo mottob eht dehcuot
tub drabbacs eht tog ev’I kniht I“
erusserp deilppa ylelituf eh sa deifisnetni
.detserc level retaw eht sa kcab reh tsniaga desserp gniliec nweh-hguor ehT
”!rovaf eht nruter ll’I dna reggad eht em ssap woN .eerf m’I“
,siht ekil yats ot ekil d’I sa hcum sA“
,ekas nwo rieht rof sdeed suoethgir od ohw esoht rof seripsnart dooG“
.siragaS dna latrommI elbapac a dekcip eh ,yletanutroF
.su ekil serutaerc rof efilretfa on si erehT“
.esool tonk eht teg t’nac I
.yaw evag eenk tfel reh sa
snopaew larutan reh htiw xnyl eht ta dehsals yllaturb ehs ,daeherof reh no sdnuow laicifrepus morf gnilkcirt doolb eht morf dednilB
”.sevil gnol yllarutannu sevlesmeht nopu wotseb dluoc yeht deveileb yeht ,sdog eht ot decifircas yeht esoht morf ytilativ gniward yB
”.traeh ruoy ni erif hcum esnes I
.htuoS levart lliw uoy ,ereht morF
.kcab s’lacarac eht revo ti gnignils erofeb edisni gnihtemos dekcut partaS ehT .kcap derettab s’nirihS htiw denruter ilieamsE rednammoC sa tnemeticxe reh laecnoc ot gniyrt ,deksa aetnaP ”?em htiw nirihS ekat I yaM“  ”.yadot
.rewop nwo reh rednu dnats ot deganam ehs sa denaorg lacarac eht ,stlas rogiv eht fo ffihw peed a gnikat retfA
.dnegel si modsiw siH .lla retfa ,partaS eht si eH“  ”.wenk
.spil sih revo eugnot sih dekcilf ylgnikcom demhsaH
.deilper demhsaH
”!lakcaj gniknits a fo nosdnarg ,tip a ni eiD“ 	 ”?mh ,neht
.pmil tnew dna depsag demhsaH
.thgin sselduolc a no noom eht sa thgirb dna raelc doots—
sa thgiled htiw dehctiwt sreksihw sih
.ylsuovren deplug aetnaP
ti daerps drapoel ehT .ssomdoolb dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
”,dessap eh erofeb mih etagorretni ot elbanu…saw I“
”.htaerb ward llits ew elihw sevlesruo rof rewop rieht fo parcs a ekat si od nac ew llA
rorroh htiw emocrevo saw ehs ,thgil mid eht ot detsujda ylluf seyE
āhnA fo sdnasuoht
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
desoppus erew uoY“
diuqil gnizeerf sa
.reviR sirgiT eht fo sknab eht gnola dekats
.nepo ti gnikcarc erofeb worbeye na dekcoc ehS
”?thgirla uoy erA !nirihS…aetnaP“  ”.enog
”.taht eganam nac I kniht I .partaS ,uoy knahT“
ruo smees ti ,yletanutroF
,traeh gnirednuht s’nirihS fo noitasnes eht yb dehtooS
.dekabnus tlef ylneddus skeehc reh sa
.NGISLLAC htiw
.llaw eht tsniaga gnipmuls ,deilper nirihS ”,partaS ,seY“  ”.kraM reh denrae sah ehs taht sraeppa tI .latrommI ruoy ot kaeps I elihw sdnuow ruoy fo emos ot dnet ilieamsE rednammoC teL“
.reed wollaf deuqebrab htiw deffuts yletelpmoc
”.doolb ruoy…evah lliw eW
”?pu su gniyt elihw dekoolrevo evah thgim demhsaH
,sretaw gnilriws eht ta dezag partaS ehT ”.rebmahc
.ni dehsur ti sa edis sih otno xnyl eht gnipeews ylraen
ygolohtna wen eht morf
.swodahs eht morf tuo gnipael ,detuohs demhsaH
poord ot sdileye yvaeh reh dewolla aetnaP
.ytiralc neddus fo tnemom a ni deksa aetnaP
saw tI .mlap reh ssorca racs gnimaelg a laever ot yawa ecitluop eht deppirts partaS eht sa denediw seye reH
reh fo tserc eht gnola tuo deffup ruF
ot emit on saw erehT
llaw eht denimaxe ylsuoiditsaf eh ,sdnob reh thgif ot deunitnoc aetnaP elihW
.rebmahc depmarc eht gnitanimulli ,efil ot dezalb hcrot A
.eof ro dneirf erew yeht fi llet ot elbissopmi saw ti hguoht
.dehguoc dna pu doots—segadnab nenil ni derevoc won—nirihS ”?partaS
.elttem ruoy fo tset yhtrow a saw ti
,drawrof delwarc thgil eht gniraeb erugif dekaolc-der ehT
.eert mlap etad a tsniaga ,kcab-ot-kcab ,rehtegot despalloc yehT
.siragaS ,llew reh dednefed uoY“
.sgnidnib s’aetnaP hguorht was ot edalb eht desu lacarac eht ,retal tnemom A
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb ”kraM s’partaS ehT“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
”.erudne lliw ereh hpmuirt ruo fo trap a woN .erehT“
…rouqil dekips-enabneh yb suoicsnocnu deggurd erew seoreh ruo erehw regnahffilc a no dedne eW
siragaS reh fo keehc eht desserac spil s’aetnaP ,esolc ni gninaeL
leehw retaw llams A
hsag tlob-gninthgil
,eleetS ”xuaF“ samohT yb
,laes s’partaS eht htiw
”.hcraes eht htiw pleh ot deen I“
”?reggad ym hcaer uoy nac…naC“
.ecalp ni etalp tsehc reh ylno gnivael
.noitcart tsol swalc toof reh sa tsuj
revir eht morf retaw digirf thguorb tcudeuqa enots A
gnidnirg dehctip-wol a sa
.nevenu dna deggaj ecamirg reh gnivael
.ecalp siht ni deripsnart dah tahw fo
.reh ediseb drapoel eht ta gnicnalg ,dias nirihS
”?reed wollaf deuqebrab taht rof tuo uoy ekat nac I ebyam…siht fo tuo teg ew fI“
,emoh aetnaP trocse I ecno ilieamsE rednammoC ot
”.hctaw ot hcamots ym snrut syawla
”.evigrof ot gnihton si erehT“
.kcap reh denimaxe ehs sa worbeye na dekcoc nirihS
hself reh hguorht erot swalc s’nirihS fo eno sa hgiht s’aetnaP hguorht tohs niap gniraeS
.enots kcils eht no esahcrup rof thguof swap s’nirihS ,shgiht reh deppirg tnerruc eht sa gnitnurG   ”!tihS“
.noitrexe htiw gnitnap ,detnurg nirihS ”,thgiR“
,redluohs reh revo mra s’nirihS gnuls ehs sa sffur keehc reh htaeneb gnihsulB
.tiurf der suoicsul a fo tuo knuhc a erot eh sa dehcnurc ylduol hself elppA
.thgirpu niamer ot delggurts aetnaP ”.partaS…uoy knahT“  ”.elttem
.ratrom eht ssorca swalc sih gniparcs yb
s’erehT .ereh morf ti ekat em teL“
”.htaerb ruoy evaS“
.yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb
”.neht ,skram ruo evael su teL“
.hgis tfos a htiw tsehc s’aetnaP otno despalloc lacarac ehT  .detuohs aetnaP
,gniliec eht ssorca dennacs aetnaP
”?tahw rof dna ,tuo deffuns sevil ynam oS
.noitsuahxe morf tuo delwarps drapoel eht sa enola esor eh
”!dneirflrig ym morf yawa teG“
drawpu flesreh werht nirihS
.edis reh tsniaga esolc desserp ydob mraw s’nirihS sa dehgis drapoel eht
”.tneper uoy fi efil ruoy eraps lliw eH
.seye nrets htiw ezag reh tem eh sa
.enots eht otni devrac—asonyeR—
.rebmahc yrev siht ni denword erew
.noissimmoc ruoy gniraeb evirra lliw silopesreP morf telbat yalc a ,emit ’skeew wef a nI .seY“
,srehto fo hcaorppa eht delangis yawllah eht nwod erehwemos morf romra rehtael fo gnidduht evitcnitsid ehT
.tlis eht hguorht gnihtyna ees dluoc aetnaP taht ton—retaw eht htaeneb efink eht revuenam dna yrt
.htgnerts evah llits uoy elihw ,gniog teg ,woN“
.relaeh lairepmi eht ees tub od ot uoy rof erom gnihton
.laes ot ssomdoolb tsenif eht neve rof egral oot raf saw tI
.ecno ta ereht nirihS trocse ,esaelP“ .seye nrets htiw aetnaP ot denrut drapoel ehT  .detnurg nirihS ”—I ,partaS“
.kcab sih morf aetnaP egdolsid ot deirt eh sa
.taorht sih ssorca
,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
ilieamsE rednammoC ecno ,delaes elpmet siht evah lliw I“
”?!uoy era yllaer ohW
yromem dnoyeb esoht yb nrow sevoorg deggar otni swalc sih dekcol eh ,troffe htiw gnitnurG
.detoor flesmih peek ot
.elpmet eht edistuo fo espmilg a thguac d’ehs kaolcdlog eht neeb evah tsum eh dezilaer aetnaP .nordluap sih no drauG s’partaS eht fo ligis daeh s’drapoel eht gniraeb
”,uoy esoohc d’I…enoyna htiw nword ot esoohc ot dah I fi ,hguohT !sknahT“
”?swap gnidloh elihw srats eht ta ezaG“
revel llams a dnuof eh
partaS eht ,slakcaj nedlog erom owt yb detrocsE
nirihS dna aetnaP ,emit tsaL
.ssensuoicsnoc deniager ehs sa detuohs nirihS
”.hserf si tuc eht elihw kraM ruoy laes tsum I“
eceip elpmas a gnireffo
sregnif gnilbmert reH
”,ecitsuj s’adzaM aruhA raef ton od I
.retaw daert ot tsuj dessessop siragaS eht elcsum fo ecnuo yreve koot tI
.noziroh eht htaeneb gnippid
”,tser ot deen uoY“
,esolc ni denael nirihS ”.latrommI
.kcen sih ni yretra na thguac walc xedni s’nirihS sa denaorg demhsaH  .demaercs nirihS
.etag eciuls eht denepo demhsaH ,drawnwod revel eht gnikcilF
.wenk eh woh rednow tsuj I
.thgil erom ni tel ot gnitalid slipup
?thgir ,etad ruo sa stnuoc siht sseug I“
”?he ,epacse ew retfa rof htaed citnamor a fo klat eht evas s’teL“
,regna ni kcab reh dehcra yllautcnitsni aetnaP
dnuof eb nac seirots sih fo eroM
.gnitnilg yltbus stsirw sih no selgnab revlis hcir
edalb eht dehtaehs ehs
dog yttep ruoy ot sreganeet gnicifircas dna sniur ni gnidiH“ .rehtruf tib
peed a gnilaever
.don gnivorppa na nirihS evag eh sa denethgirb ecaf s’drapoel ehT
”!ereh fo tuo teg s’tel woN .ti toG“
”.stnuoc ti kniht
.latrommI gnuoy ,reh retfa kool oD
tnetxe eurt eht dezilaer ehs sa
,emit fo segavar eht erudne dluow gnivargne eht taht deifsitas saw ehs ecnO
.taeh htiw delkcirp niaga ecno niks reh sa romra deggolretaw reh ffo gnippirts ekil tlef aetnaP ,ylnedduS .ytinrete na demees tahw rof sesiri neerg-dlareme etaciled reh fo liated yreve revo decart lacarac ehT .seye s’aetnaP teem ot gninrut ,dias nirihS
noitcaer kciuq s’aetnaP ylnO
”.tsal ruoy ehtaerb uoy erofeb nossel yrotsih elttil a rof emit s’ereht kniht I“
nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI
.yltnatiseh deksa lacarac eht
reh ot esolc os gnikorts sdap wap ’siragaS reh fo gnileef eht deyojne evah thgim drapoel eht ,secnatsmucric retteb nI
”.ecifircas āhnA .ecifircaS“
.yawa tpews gnieb diova ot tsop gninword eht ot ylthgit gnilc ot dah aetnaP ,hguorht ekorb nirihS ecnO
,redluohs s’xnyl eht otni swalc reh knis dluoc aetnaP erofeB ”!ti nO“  ”!luos ruoy ekat sdog eht yaM !amzag aY“ .drows
”.lufrednow…sdnuos tahT“
,romra deggolretaw reh gnidracsid nageb ehS
.elzzum s’nirihS fo pit eht htaeneb laihp rehtael llams a dleh partaS ehT
.moorhsum nretnal-’o-kcaj a fo sllig eht ekil gniwolg yltbus seye nedlog sih ,rewop lacitsym etaidar ot demees eH
.sgniK fo gniK eht fo tnavres dna doolb ym fo doolb ,esiR“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.noitamrofni htiw partaS eht ylppus ot hguone gnol evil uoy referp d’I .uoy pleh em teL“ .delworg nirihS
,revo meht dekool
.rekcepxo suoiciv a ekil sdnuow hself reh ta erot eh sa tluassa sih no nwod gnilbuod
.ylrettib dehgual demhsaH
”.yllautca ,tol a etiuq taht ekil d’I…taht ekil d’I“
yah deird fo roloc eht kaolc a htiw lakcaj nedlog A
”.dnatsrednu reven ll’uoy taht won ees I“
,noititsrepus ylerem ro laer erew seuqinhcet decnavda rehtehw ,cigam doolb dehcraeser evah I hguohT“
”?thgir ,rehtegot siht ni er’eW“
.hgis detsuahxe na htiw daeh reh derewol aetnaP
.enog s’eH .ti nmaD“
,eroc reh ni aibohportsualc gnisir eht tsniaga delggurts ehS
”,era ew adzaM aruhA yB“
.tnerrot gnilriws eht evoba sehcni ylno
.ot emac ehs sa derettum
.specib reh ssorca dellor retaw eht sa
,thgilrats gnilkniwt fo lufpac a ekiL
.cigam doolb fo mrof detsiwt a fo srenoititcarp
”!gnihtyreve deniur dna emac partaS ruoy ,nehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.shtym eht ni deveileb ylsuoivbo xnyl siht tub…yas tonnac I
,hpmuirt ni denraE“
,yllaer ,eh saw
.melatrommI namaZ aetnaP ,edirp htiw kraM ruoy raeW
siht…llitS .dluohs ti sA“
.llewriats eht fo pets pot eht htiw neve won
,segas doolb eht wels partaS eht nehw tsol saw tahw ecalper lliw gnihtoN“
ruoy etic ton od
.eson kcalb-knip reh fo pit eht no tser ot gnimoc erofeb ruf reh hguorht drawnwod dekaerts ti
,ytilatipsoh ym detpecca t’ndah uoy fi…llitS .evïan os etiuq
”?srehto htiw deripsnoc eh rehtehw yas xnyl siht diD
,taocrednu reh morf delkcirt retaw sa kcab reh otno dellor ehS
,pets tsrif eht otno flesmih deggard demhsaH
.ydaerla uoy dlot I“
”!uoy dniheb thgir m’I ;tsrif og uoY“ .detuohs nirihS
.em ot htiaf detropmi
”.srodirroc sti fo hcraes lluf a seesrevo
,sllaw eht gninroda shpargotcip eht morf gnigduJ
.segde eht dnuora tuo yarg ot noisiv reh desuac daeh reh gnitfiL
ohw…ecnenitrepmi ym esucxe dluow uoy fI“  ”.uoy knaht-
ecnereffid eht swonk eH“
”,yltnailav thguof uoY“
.nip ssarb dedorroc a htiw
.latrommI ym ,enim lla si erusaelp ehT“
enots eht ni deruces ekats nedoow a ot reh gnidnib ,tsaf reh dleh epor gnidleiynu ehT
”,ytilaturb tnegludni-fles dna ecneloiv yrassecen neewteb
.seye sih gnillor ,deilper demhsaH ”,ylsuoivbO“
,dekramer nirihS ”,evom dluohs ew
.ereh nwod uoy gnirb ot snaem dezilivic ssel yolpme ot dah evah dluow I
.wap gnideelb reh ot erusserp gniylppa
”!tius gnorts ruoy neeb syawla s’tahT !knihT“
ti…won gniog eb ll’I .htaerb peed a ekat dna xaler tsuj
rats gnillaf a ekil seye sih morf gnidaf thgil ,depsag demhsaH
.gniliec eht morf esacriats enots a fo tnecsed eht dedlareh
”?ti t’nsi ,won si ecifircas eht tahw uoy ot suoivbo s’tI
.dlohekohc a ni nirihS tup ot gnithgif ,delworg dehsaH
.reh dnuora ssenkrad gnihsurc eht otni delley ehs
,partaS eht fo eman eht nI“
.slipup dettils rieht nopu llef thgilhcrot gnikcilf sa drawpu dezag riap ehT
.taorht s’nirihS dnuora mraerof sih dehcnic demhsaH sa revo-delbuod tfel saw ehs ,ria rof gnipsaG
ereh detsixe noitazilivic taerg A“
drows sih uoy reffo ot ereht uoy teem skaolcdlog ym fo eno evah ll’I
”!esaelp ,pleh elttil A“
etag eciuls eht evoba detnuom
.iotanahtA eht fo eno sa uoy kram llahs dnuow siht morf racs eht
.ti ot dne na tup eh dalg m’I“
”.noitidnoc ym ni rethgif elba tsom eht ton m’I .tniop ekat uoY“
.tnemom a rof tsuj—
.dedda ylluftcepser aetnaP
”.tnavres ruoy
eznorb tsenif eht fo romra ni dalc drapoel taerg a—
ruf deggolretaw hguorht dekorts
,pirg denekaew s’demhsaH htaeneb morf tuo gnimriuqS
,deppots gnidnirg eht ecnO
.dehsiuqnav gnol thguoht I eof a tsniaga
;retaw eht thgif ot ton uoy esivda I
ecitluop eht fo erom elttil a gniylppa ,dias partaS eht
.droc eht gnireves elihw
”.etad a s’tI“
”!ruc ,siht terger ot gniog er’uoY“
,swolb yrotailater sih tlef ylerab aetnaP ,iotanahtA eurt a fo egardoolb eht ni desremmI
.worb reh otno gniliec eht morf yllufecarg llef telpord retaw a sa deknilb nirihS
nirihS deerf drapoel eht ,egde prahs-dekciw eht no mlap reh gnittuc yllatnediccA
.ratsgnillaF demhsaH ma I“
troppus rof aetnaP dnuora mra reh werht ehS
.anera gniniart eht ni drows deddap a erew ti hguoht sa gnidnal hcae
,kcap reh rof rodirroc eht dennacs nirihS sA  ”.llaf
”,dne na ta si sihT“   .dnuow sih ot
dessobme hcuop rehtael egral a saw pot eht ta deltseN
”.dednem ylluf evah seirujni s’nirihS litnu
.llewriats eht fo pot eht ta yawhcra eht hguorht dekcud demhsaH
yawllah eht fo dne eht ot pmil lacarac eht depleh aetnaP
ecitsuj enivid evah llahs drawer luof fo hcraes rof live od ohw esohT
.tsehc reh ni gnisir
.thgir sgniht tes ot
lakcaj nedlog llat a ,sniatpac sih
,deraperp I egnellahc eht ton si siht hguohT
.tuoba gnihsarht yltnetopmi ,delrans aetnaP
cinap eht otni gnivig diova ot delggurts aetnaP
elttil erac sdog ehT
sregnif reh leef ylerab dluoc aetnaP
.htuoy fo evol tserup eht htiw dellif traeh reh sa
.elzzum sih gniffuc nageb dna dnuorg eht ot demhsaH delpparg ehs ,niap dna egar fo erutxim a htiw gnihceercS
?ynomerec laiciffo na eb llits ereht lliW“
”!daetsni eerf reggad eht tuc ot evah ot gniog m’I
,teef reh ot debmilc aetnaP
.latrommI na fo sutats eht flesruoy rof denrae uoy ,os gniod nI
.redluohs reh fo taem eht decreip ti
.htmraw etareneg ot yletarepsed thguof ydob reh ni elcsum yreve sa sredluohs reh hguorht tohs sromerT
.dnim reh hguorht degrus snihprodne fo hsur a sa hpmuirt fo wolg eht ni deksab aetnaP  	”.melatrommI
troper lluf a evig lliw I taht drow ym evah uoY“
.llaf lliw....partaS ehT“
”!reh mrah…uoy tel…t’now I“
,roolf eht morf pu reggad s’demhsaH gnikciP
.krab derocs morf pas rebbur ekil seye gninrub sih morf deppird tpmetnoC
aetnaP ”,kcuF“  2 fo 2 traP
,llewriats eht fo pot eht ta gnitlaH  .deilper aetnaP
tsom dna tsehgih eht saw tI
.snodnet yna dereves t’ndah ehs ,peed saw tuc eht hguohT
”.efas er’uoy ,sdog eht knahT“
.daeh reh koohs dna dehgis ehs ,kcen s’xnyl eht fo edis eht tsniaga regnif a gnicalP
”.sdnal suorehcaert hcus hguorht uoy trocse ot
yruf war eht ekil
reve ma I .partaS ,uoy knahT“
”?drapoel gnuoy ,seil uoy def I kniht uoy oD
.remmahxuaf/resu/ten.ytiniffaruf.www ta
.daeh sih koohs partaS ehT
”.era uoy ereh tey dnA“
”!uoy detsurt evah dluohs reven I“
.rufdaeh s’drapoel eht hguorht wap a gnihsurb ylrednet
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.rewop eurt ruoy ot semulov skaeps
.thgiew s’lacarac eht raeb ot hguone htgnerts dnuof wohemos latrommI eht
.selkcunk erab reh otni gniggid sretnilps s’tsop gninword eht ,delrans aetnaP
.htmraw ylrehtaf htiw dereyal eciov ,dias partaS eht
eb ot owt uoy detcepxe t’ndah I taht timda tsum I“
”.kcal stseirp tsehgih ruoy neve rewop evah I“
.drawkcab dereggats ehs sa ylsuonimo dekaerc sbiR
.revo deleek ylneddus ehs sa detnurg nirihS ”—I .ti fo noitnem on edam eh ,toofa ycaripsnoc a si ereht fI
.enots drah eht otno gnignulp morf reh detneverp
.teef s’aetnaP ta tser ot gnimoc erofeb
”!siht pots ot etal oot ton s’tI“
”!ytrid swap ym teg ot evah I woN“
,srosicni reh fo eno deppihc dah enabneh eht morf revo gnileeK
.esacriats eht otno gnilggurts elihw depsag aetnaP
,thgiew reh gniraeb ylidaeR
.nus noonretfa etal eht fo htmraw eht otni dna
.cigam doolb fo krow lufituaeb
deppit-evif a ekil tsehc s’demhsaH gnihsals swalc
”.tcerroc yletulosba
.detnurg nirihS ”!ti no gnikroW“
smra ni delliks eno deen lliw uoY .draug truoc eht morf reh llacer lliw I“ 	  ”?esaelP“
kaolc sih fo euh nosmirc ehT
,edis sih ot llef wap siH
”?rof desu saw elpmet siht tahw wonk uoy oD“
”.dedeen ton saw noitnevretni
deraeppasid uoy sa noos sa em detrela ilieamsE rednammoC“
”?huh ,rehtegot htuoS eht ot yenruoj a…oS“
”.uoy edisgnola gnithgif naht kraM s’partaS eht denrae evah rehtar d’I yaw rehtona fo kniht t’nac I“
.yhport raw a sa latrommI reh ot ti detneserp dna
”..pihsrentrap enif a rof ekam owt uoY
,xnyl eht ta mgelhp degnit-doolb fo knuhc a dekwah ehs ,htgnerts reh gnirehtaG
.htgnerts laitnatsbus fo lleps a rof rewop hguone evah dluow eh taht depoh eH“
,dehsiugnitxe saw tekcop ria reh retfa tnemom A
”.aetnaP gnitcetorp no desucof oot saw I“
.gniliec eht raen delaecnoc
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
gnihtemos ereht sI“ .detuohs nirihS
.kcab reh dniheb ylmrif swap s’drapoel eht dnuob droc pmeh tsiom fo htgnel A
”,partaS ,modsiw ruoy gnirahs elbatrofmoc er’uoy fI“
.snoitaerc latrom rieht rof
I…drocer eht rof tsuj dnA
.partaS ,ton yletanutrofnU“
.dehsinav tniartser s’drapoel eht lla ,tnatsni taht nI
.stsirw sih no ruf deyd-anneh htiw
taht ni denword evah dluow ecalp ruoy ni srehto ynaM
.elzzum reh otni taem fo knuh a deppop ehs sa eugnot reh ssorca demossolb ecips hciR
.tsehc reh fo retnec eht otni drawkcab demmals leeh sih
”.hgiht renni ym ot dehcatta llits s’ti kniht I“
T“ .erob rehtom reh eno eht ekil yltcaxe kraM a
,elpmet eht otni nwod
tsirw s’nirihS dezies drapoel eht
.drawer fo hcraes eht rof ton
āhnA denmednoc fo sdleif ta dezag eh ,dnah eno ni depsarg ylmrif tnedirT
”.regnad ni aetnaP ecalp ot naem ton did I“
noitarecal s’aetnaP ssorca
a spets eht gnirewol noitulover hcae ,tfahs gnitator a ot rewop derrefsnart
.niorg s’xnyl eht ot woble prahs a gnireviled ,detuohs nirihS
,hceercs dezinoga na tuo tel demhsaH
.flesruoy llesrednu t’noD“
”.regnil ot owt uoy rof ecalp on si
.etsap nworb-anneis a htiw derevoc yletelpmoc saw ti litnu
”!ma I evïan woh tsuj uoy wohs ll’I dna kcab rihsmahs ym em eviG“
.srae reh fo pit eht evoba sehcni wef a tsuj gniliec eht
erew yehT .eripmE eht erofeb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
rednammoC ,noissergsnart ym evigroF“
.sreppihsrow fo sdnasuoht fo hcuot eht yb htooms nrow neeb dah taht llaw fo hctap a otni seman rieht dehctarcs ylhguor nirihS
sbreh fo dnelb dercas a htiw doolb sih dexim eh ,israF ni noitatnacni cidolem dna hcir a gnirumruM
”,ytisnetni dlof-eerht htiw
.deraperp si ti ecno mrofienuc eht revo kool lliw I“  ”.partaS
”.lla ta efil on si efil latrom A“
redluohs s’nirihS no dnuow eht ot
.nam gnivrats a ot daerb dekab-hserf ekil saw
.su taefed…reven lliw uoY“
.edam erew secifircas reporp eht sa gnol os efil gnitsalreve detnarg taht ymehcla dercas a fo wenk segas doolb tneicna ehT“
.tnerrot dedaeh-etihw eht morf reh deggut dna
tseb eht rof saw ti spahreP
.wap reh no hsag dekciw eht no tser ot emac yehT
.sdnas tresed eht htaeneb erehwemos gnirrits ssenkrad fo rae ym dehcaer sah droW
,asonyeR fo elpmeT eht deretne
.gnihtemos rof gnitnuh fi sa dnuorg eht ssorca gnipeews liat sih
.eerf kaerb ot gnithgif elihw delwoy yltneloiv nirihS sa enips
meht dnuora lla gnilriws tnerrot gnigar eht ,rebmahc kcalb-hctip eht ni enola meht tfel eH
fo eno htiw kool denrecnoc a derahs partaS ehT
.mraerof s’aetnaP ssorca swalc delemane sih hsurb ot nwod tauqs ot dah partaS eht ,drapoel eganeet eht revo gnirewoT
yltnailav thguof uoY
,gnihcraes fo setunim wef a retfA
”—doolb ruo gnisu ,oS“
.drapoel eht fo tnorf ni secap wef a tpek nirihS ,swalc reh gnihtaehsnU ”.ecalp ni dennip si duorhs lairub rieht litnu thgif eht fo tuo t’nsi iotanahtA nA
”.tey regnad fo tuo ton er’eW“
,detsuahxe dna gnizeerf saw ehs hguohT
”!dnuora emit siht evarg yretaw a morf uoy llup em teL“
.eripmE naisreP eht fo nus mraw eht rednu
,rovaf eht denruter ehs sa ruf reh hguorht dehsug doolB
.mraerof sih ssorca ylthgil reggad a werd partaS ehT  ”.ydaer m’I“
erofeb reggad derehtaew s’demhsaH fo tnilg llud eht deretsiger ylerab nirihS  ”!eid ot
.dewob nirihS ”,ilieamsE
.asonyeR fo elpmeT eht otni
meht no nwod thguorb
,retaw eht ni tuoba dehsarht riap eht sA