reh sekam ,ti hcuot
.retniw rof desserd yletomer t’nsaw ehs ,tihS
.won thgir ,won thgir
elttem reh stset gnilgdelf eht woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.ni gnilttes saw noitartsurf dna ,no gard ot gninnigeb saw thgin ehT
.ereh tuo hcruhC eht etah yeht -htolcder
yoj tnerever fo regnif a tlef ehs taht ,reh fo tnaw
.traeh daed reh gnola flesti nur
.edalb gnileud a sa drah dna rednels ,xof der a saw ehS
yab ta regnuh gnitnelernu reh peek dluoc ehs erus saw ehs litnu yawa eno hcae deniard tenniL retsiS
.flesreh pots ehs taht
”gninrom worromot ksa ,etal s’tI“ ekil gnihtemos dias meht fo hcaE
.secips ,emoh sih morf sreppep dah ew
enilpicsid fo rettam a saw ti tub ,nrael dluoc
.thgilnoom yhctap eht ni serutplucs-wons ekil gniremmilg sterrut yrovi sti htiw ,woleb ytic taerg eht ta nwod gnitniop ,walc gnol eno dednetxe retsaM ehT
.evila saw ehs nehw enog evah reven dluoc ,nees reven dah ehs secalP .ereht tuo sdnal tnereffid ynaM
:dias retsam eht ,emit gnol a ekil tlef tahw retfA
,s’esle enoemos saw efil-non sihT
tnatsni na ni dnA
.nam gnuoy eht fo gniward …“
.seye reh tfil ton did gnilgdelf eht tub
-tnenamrep eb yam egamaD
.em rof kooc dluoc eH .ecaep ni evil dluoc ew ,segaw ruo dah ew ,won su rof emoh a dah I tub
.ssorc gnikcuf eht nwod tup lliw yeht ylno fi
tlef ehS .seripmav ton dna ,stirips live ffo evird ot edam neeb dah yeht tub ,htiaf fo slobmys sa detnuoc sgniht hcuS
.tsefinam dluow gnitalpmetnoc saw ehs ecneloiv eht ,gnihtemos knird
.kcen reh revo ti spils ,gnikahs ,dna niahc nori eht sekat ehS
…desu eh esarhp eht saw tahw ,ho …dias tseirp der eht dnA
.drah yrev ti ot gnulc ehs ,llits tub
nwod gnignah sgnaf gnol-oot esoht htiw delims dna dias d’eH ”.yreV“
.esaesid dna sseneldi ni sevil rieht etsaw ohw nem enots ot elpoep ruo fo motsuc eht saw ti taht dias egduj eht dna
.thgilpmal htiw mraw yawrood a nihtiw morf reh ot wap sih devaw taoc s’reniram a ni retto dlo nA
.aes ta neeb d’ew elihw yawa dessap dah rehtaf ym taht demrofni saw I ,trop otni emac ew nehW
-etaf saw ti thguoht I
,sgnilgdelf ynam rof esac eht si sa tuB .yllausu
,syawla em snruB .yawa og
.erutrot fo skeew retfa etarelot ot
.elttirb dna deyarf won saw tub ,tfos neeb ecno dah taht
”stnallegalf uoy rof retlehs on ev’eW“ ro
”.mih gninots nageb yeht erofeb sserd ot emit dah yldrah I .tneserp saw egduj ehT“
.latrommi saw ehs woN
,igam eht fo eno tsniaga
.htolc eht fo sretsis wollef reh ,lepahc eht ta efil fo dluoc ehs tahw tuoba deklat ehS .gnol thgin lla deklat yehT   .ti deganam ehs
.sriats eht no mih dniheb reh raeh ro ees ton did ylluS
na hsurc ot tna na gniksa ekil saw tI
retsiS“   .gnikniht pots ot dah ehs neht dna
dlo na rof gnikool ma I“
.erew sgniht woh yllareneg saw siht ,yretsanom reh fo sllaw eht edistuO
,revewoh ,regnuh reH
.elims kaew a reh evag ylluS
.esuap A ”.llits latrom sI“
.gninoitseuq s’owt ro ruoh na fo tuo gnihtemos teg dluoc ehs tsael ta tub
,noissapmoc sselmohtaf fo nam a saw retsam ehT .selur tcnitsni ,stiw rieht peek ohw esoht rof neve dna—
ydob deltnamsid sih fo thguoht ehS
,rallec eht ot yaw eht reh dewohs retto eht
I dna ,sraey neves rof rehtegot delias eW .gnihtoN“
,reh rof tiaw yltneitap dna pots ot degilbo saw eh ,neht dna woN
,dias ylluS ”.sdneirf tseB“
.niaga stiurf reh dleiy yaM
ekats a hsup lliw ew ro
.tsal ta dias ehS
,cinap a otni reh derrits thguoht ehT
.tenniL retsiS ma I .ylluS .rM ,elbatirahc
.niaga ytic eht ta nwod detniop eH ”.lliK
,laticer ehT .snoitanalpxe ehT .reyarp ehT .ygrutil ehT
.ylredro dna elpmis ,emoh elbmuh eht ta dnuora ylgnignol derats ehS
,sneppah ti sa ,saw eH“
,wohemos tub ,tnahpele
,rorret fo lluf dna trohs neeb dah feiht a sa efil reH
.esaelp ,ni emoC“ gnillac
flesreh delliw dna ,erutpircs no detatidem ,peed dehtaerb ehS
,eye sih no mrof ot gninetaerht raet a llems dluoc ehS .semit lareves yawa kool ot dah nexiv eht dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
yawa nweh saw tser eht lla nehw senob reh ot gnulc dah taht ytinamuh fo parcs enasni emoS
,boj eht rof em diap eh -ekops ylerab eW
.retteb wonk ot demees lla yehT
sgnaf reh morf loord fo sgnirts hguoht dnA .ediw nepo elzzum reh htiw ydob gnipeels sih revo dehcnuh redniamer s’thgin eht fo tsom tneps retsis doog ehT
saw noitavrats reh fo edutingam ehT
,tseirp taht togrof reven I tuB“
.mees yam ti mirg revewoh ,eno siht yojne lliw serutaerc-thgin wollef sih sepoh ohw ,ijustihoK yb ”eripmaV eht dna nexiV ehT“
yreV“   ”.tluC“ .sliaf eH
,kool ot gnivah fo taht sespilce niap eht dna ti dloh
.denoitseuq eb ot tnaw
.mih no pu kaens ot eganam dluoc ehs nehw ,ruf kcen sih ni eson dloc reh gnikcits yb hgual mih ekam dluoc ehs woH .tfos dna mraw
t’ndid ehs fi esuaceb ,sey dias ehs dna deltsihw top ehT
.ecno ta dias reve sah eh tsom eht si tI ”.ffo meht ekat
.dlrow eht lla ni stnaryt-rerecros tsetaerg eht eb ot denokcer
.esruoc fo ,seY“ .noitanimaxe nA
?ekahs dna maof dna ezies reh hctaw ot erusaelp a ti sI
”.ruoh enO .kaerb lliw nwaD“
”.reilrae denoitnem I ’nrut doog‘ taht
htrib ylemit htiw htrae yldnik tahT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ti ot degnoleb eh nettogrof dah ynam dna ,eromyna nwot ot emac reve yldrah eH
.demusnoc ton si tey dna snrub ehs skeew roF .peels tnacs reh
,llef thgin nehw ti was ehs syawla dna
,etteutats llams a no deregnil ezag s’gnilgdelf ehT
.drow hguone etilop a dnif ot selggurts eH
.flesreh deyarteb ehs dna ,seye reh fo part gnir-der eht ni thguac noom ,mih ta dekool tenniL .tlobrednuht a fo egassap eht ekil reh ni evom raef tlef ehs dna
”.erif eht yb flesruoy mraw emoC“
.sretsis eht si ti semitemoS
”?emos tnaw uoy oD .aet ym erahs nac I taht ,esruoc fo ,oot yppaH“
”.si eh niatrec ylevitaleR“ .dias ehS ”.haeY“
”eripmaV eht dna nexiV ehT“   yojne esaelP
.noitnevni gnicnivnoc
.srae sti pu dekcirp
.gnilgdelf sih ni raef detah retsaM
,tnaw yeht revetahW .dnim ot semoc revetahw ,seisatnaf elbidercni ,seil dna
.oga sraey saw tI“
.aisahpA .aera s’acorB
.eirever reh fo tuo deppans ehs ”—hO“
.dias ylluS ”?tenniL
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.sretnec egaugnal stceffA .sriapmi
neeb ev’I dna nrevat a fo tuo gnimoc taoc ym koot enoemos ,yrros etiuq m’I
”.liated enif taht lla htiw sniap taerg yrev koot enoemoS
”.gnihtyreve dnA .srevol dnA“
,”?rereffus siht fo htaed eht detnioppa sah nam tahW“
.drow yreve rof gninetsil
.dias ehs lla saw ”,retsam ,seY“
”.efil rof sdneirf emaceb I dna ayilU ,hcum os etam tsrif taht detah I
,loord reh ekam ot gninetaerht saw siht fo niap ylevol ehT
.sbos ehs nehw reh sdloh eh sa sgniw sih fo rehtael mraw ehT
.niap nevE .detsaw si taht
”.retteb swonk ylluS dlO
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.diov eht yb dewollaws neeb dah mih dniheb srats eht fi sa saw ti dna
.nials esiwrehto saw ehs ro reh koot nus eht litnu htrae siht klaw dluow ehS
.erofeb reh rof ti enod reve dah
”,seY“    ”—tsew eht tuB“
,derutseg eH ”…esuaceb ,llew
***  .regnuh ot niaga ekowa ehs dna
eht ffo kcurts dna drows sih werd tseirp ehT
yllautnevE  .dnilb og ti ekam ro ,ti tsiwt thgim ehs hcihw yb sdohtem eht delaever tey ton dah
.thgindoog reh dib eh neht dna ,peels ot dehsiw ehs erehw
.olocuB droffaR ,reknab
.seye reh fo sespmilg tneuqerf erom dna erom thguac dna
.dereffo saw eno nehw nwod tas yletilop tenniL dna
,staorht rieht ni tseretni gnikrul reh desnes ecneidua reh ,drow yreve htiw tub
,ytiniffaruF no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,deen taerg ni neve ,eromyna reh ot gniyfsitas yletomer t’nerew yehT
nrut doog a em did hcruhC deR dlo ehT“
.esirnus rof tiaw rO“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
eno siht piks esaelp
,htrof dna kcab delworp tirips reh nihtiw rotarepo krad ehT .niaga hcteks eht ta dekool ehs dna
,erif eht yb sriahc deretslohpu ylnialp fo riap a ot reh
.sniffoc rieht ot kcab teg tonnac dna gnuoy era yeht nehw
,esneffo reh delaecnoc dah tenniL taht dethgiled ,delkcuhc eH ”,hO“
,niar eht dna enihsnus ehT ria eltneg htiw
’.uoy tsniaga denrut si doG deR eht fo dnah ehT
,em eracs uoY“ tnaem yeht wenk ehs tuB
er’uoy kniht yehT“
ekil smees won efil ni elbacilpxeni reh ot demees hcihw taht dna
,niaga dellac-repsihw eh ”,retsiS“
.yawa knurhs dna seye reh dna ssorc reh dna sebor reh was yehT
ton did elpoepsnwot ehT
a ni tuo devil nam eht reh dlot eh dna ,droffaR tuoba mih deksa ehS
,denediw seye reH
.enola tuo lrig gnuoy roop a er’uoY .uoy ta kool tub ,ffo sregnif s’elpoep pohc ot gnikool ,srotisiuqni ruoy fo eno htiw ereh
,anueL yb uoy rof daer ,ijustihoK yb
,tnenitnoc nrehtuos tnatsid eht morf soiruc dna steknirt
tnelis tnew ylluS
”.yadot retteB“ :syas dna
.eciov s’retsaM reH
htiw spag nettogrof llif ot dah ehs nehw reh tcerroc ot hguone llew meht wonk ton did eh dna ,erutpircs fo snoitaticer wef a demrofrep ehS
.noisserpxe s’retto eht nwod gnihgiew worros sih fo tib elttil a leef dluoc tenniL tub
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT    .rits
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
…saw I esuaceb tuo mih deggard yehT
.retne ton dluoc ehs snrevat fo edistuo teerts eht no meht hctac ot dah ehs
.dellits ylwols gnikrej eht dna skaeuqs eht elihw
.meht drawot gnihcterts wodahs reh fo llihc eht ylsuoicsnocnu gnileef ,emoh deirruh yehT
.walc a htiw sdileye reh pu sleep dna daeh reh sdloh ohw ,rairf flow denam ylgnag eht si ti semitemoS
”…on er’uoy tub ,slardehtac s’daileH eht evah ro
”.em llik lliw uoy emoh ym edisni uoy tel I fi dna
.leef ot gnivrennu saw
.yllaineg liat reh gniyaws dna regnuh reh esiugsid ot gniyrt ,dias ehS
.sdrib ekil reh ta gnikcip
.tnemom a rof eceipeltnam s’retto eht no seitisoiruc eht decart seye s’tenniL  .derednaw dah ezag s’retsis doog eht taht was eh ,nwod kcab tas eh nehW ”.kcab yap I
.mih ot tnew tenniL dna
,retsaM saw eh dna ,eripmav eht saw eripmav ehT
.erutaerc-flah tenretni ruoy
,edisni tnew dna xof eht ta delims eH
.thguac saw ehS .won etal ooT
,noitseuq a saw tI ”.ylevitaleR“
.dluoc ehs tseb sa dniheb gnola deppoh ehs dna
nosneB etihW drawdE-
,seetoved senutroF ruoF eht sa etilop sa eb ton thgim yehT .oga sraey lareves
ton did retto eht
,syawla meht sraew eH .sessorc raew nac eh
.elzzum xof-gniylf rednels taht morf
.sevink neprahs ot thguat si ehs sa krad eht ni gniparcs ehT
.ecnis reve sselepoh
.oga owt ro ruoh na flesti delttes tsuj ylno dah gnineve taht llew yltcefrep wenk ehs fi neve
.delaeh tey ton dah taht dnuow a morf egadnab a ekil deppir
.nroh nretsew eht no tuo dnalemoh ym ot kcab mih koot
,rood tnorf sih hguorht thgir deklaw tenniL retsiS
.sreh neeb dah ti tub
,stceffe elpmis fo rebmun a erew htraeh eht no dna ,moor eht fo dne raf eht ta toh gninrub saw erif A
,delaeh eh retfa tub ,esruoc fo ,dluoc ew lla htiw tfel eW .emit a roF“
,tsom reh deifirret elims taht fo yromem eht ,seramthgin reh lla fO
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
dna duorp dna ekilraw saw eH
.daeh nworb ,dnuor sih deppat dna delims eH
.sdleif retniw eht nopu nwod gnikool
.eris reh dna gnilgdelf eht ,noom retniw dloc eht ni sniatnuom eht ssorca delf meht fo owt ehT
”?rehtegot krow ew nehw retteb sgniht
reh sekam rairf flow denam ehT    .etulovnoc ot yromem dna emit dewolla smaerd s’tenniL
”,oga sraey tuo devom eH“
”.aet uoy ekam ll’I
.saw eh dlo woh retsam eht deksa tenniL ,ecnO .emit dna
”.oga gnoL .ecno ssendnik a em did klof ruoy
dias dna ayilU revo doots eH
fo htron tsuj espoc
:snoitseuq reh htiw etaciled dna suoituac eb ot sniap koot tenniL ,emit hcaE
.tsrif ta thgilnoom eht fo kcirt a saw ti thguoht I .oot ,raeb kcalb dlo kciht a -tsirw eht ta egduj eht fo wap
.doG deR eht erofeb ytilimuh eht
er’uoy esuaceb eb ll’tahT“
,ecarg krad s’thgin fo lla htiw devom eH
.noituacni gnisaercni htiw ,yletarepsed gnihcraes ,steerts eht nwod dna pu detterf ehs
.krad eht ni noissapmoc egnartS
,thginot mraw eb nac uoy yppah tsuj m’I .esac yna ni ,oga sraey ynam saw taht dnA“
traeh ruoy hguorht
aneyh gnuoy a fo gniredner laocrahc ylevol a saw hcihw no ,repap fo parcs elttil a no dednal seye reH .esle gnihtemos rof dennacs ehS
”?lessev ruoy htiw od ot evah hcruhc eht did tahW“
.hguone gnol si raeY“
”?ereh si ssarG fo esreV“
.dniw eht yb yawa dehctans eb ot spil sih morf esor maets fo emulp oN .depsar eh
.tenniL dias ”?srevol erew uoY“
”eripmaV eht dna nexiV ehT“
.niaga mraw eb reven dluow ehS ”.retsis
keehc reh morf raet ydoolb elgnis a sepiw retsam reH
”—flah ni em llup ll’eh ,sugam a s’eh ,retsaM“ .meht dias ehs sa neve htuom reh otni kcab drow hcae etib ot gniyrt ,derepsihw ehs ”!dlo raey a m’I“
”.doG deR eht fo hcruhc eht ro
…ha yehT“ ,elttil a rof
”,nwot siht ni evil ot desu eh -04 ebyaM .reed elum a s’eH
”.retsiS ,gnihton wonk ew ,era ew hguoht htiaf eht ot citehtapmyS“ ro
mih tsol I“ ,dewollaws eh
,ti dloh syas eh tub
?ti yojne yeht oD
dluohs reveN .yawa seog reveN“
ediba ton did eH
.traeh ta lrig nretsae na saw ehs esuaceb dnim t’ndid ehs dna ,ayilU htiw emit sih fo seirots reh dlot ylluS ,nruter nI
.kcehc lufniap tnenamrep ni mih tpek sebor sih tuoba sniahc no erow eh sessorc-irt gnikoms ehT
.eruliaf fo secneuqesnoc eht gnirednop saw ehs elihw eht lla dna ,gnihton wenk ehs dna ,emac thgindiM
deripsni retto eht ytip raelc dloc
,kcen sih pu wed ot nwod gnuh
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
retsaM reh dna ,ecneserp reh dehtaol tcnitsni latrom tneicna emoS .thgin ta etal ylralucitraP
edih ot gnirehtob saw eH .elbidercni
.esuoh ruoy dna uoy sselb I ,doG deR eht fo hcruhC eht fo flaheb nO
”.eb ot evah t’nod uoY“
.enog dah reknab eht erehw ylesicerp wonk ot demees ydobon tub ,esnopser nommoc eht saw
.hcteks laocrahc eht ta pu ylgnignol dekool dna
.daeh sih koohs neht dna
,maerd yeht yaw eht gnimaerd ,evac gnippird dna knad emos fo kcab eht ni delruc ydaerla saw ehs
rehtael ekil eciov
on m’I .rereffus on m’I“
.smrahc ,snamsilat
dias ylluS ”.deviL“   ”?…ayilU dnA“
.ssarG fo esreV eht ot esol ot ton ,wohemos ,deganam ehs fI
ti raeh t’ndid tsomla ehS
erutaerC-flaH tenretnI ruoy ,anueL yb daeR
”.ereht tuo htaed ot ezeerf ll’uoY ?dloc uoy t’nerA“ .retto eht diaS
.hsael a no eniws laref a ni sdael
.deb ruo ni ,thgin eno su dnuof
,devirra gninrom eht nehW
,reh ot dias eH ”.wolS“
.retto eht dias ”,taerg yreV“
esle eno oN .gnilevram
”.syad eerht ni uoy tcepxE
,ijustihoK yb
”.rereffus ,eeht dnetta ecaeP
ti dloh ,doG fo eman eht ni
”!retsis ,yeH“ dellac enoemos nehw
.swen tnellecxe saw sihT
,yltnemehev ,gnitsisni saw
,won lla meht tisiv dluoc ehS
,efil dehcterw reh fo stnemom tsal eht ni retsaM eht fo sdnah eht ni
.elzzum sih ni thgir dratsab eht dekced ayilU dna ,kooc ruo eb ot saw eh sa ,sreppucs eht ot nwod og
os dna ,elbakaepsnu eht rof yticapac sih fo erawa edam neeb sah tenniL retsiS .diasnu yllatot meht tfel dah retsaM ehT
,reh deirrah seiromem dna sthguoht eht niffoc on dah ehs esuaceb dna ,gnimaerd thgilyad s’tenniL retsiS nihtiw delriws siht llA
”.elbatrofmoc erew eW
.no gnivres saw I lessev eht draoba emac eh yad eht taht werd I .ayilU s’tahT“
.yrd os saw htuom s’xof ehT
,riaf repmettA  2 fo 1 traP
”.yrros m’I …“ .llits eb ot
.sraey evif nihtiw
,em enod si ssendnik tahw dnA“
,dias I sa …tub ,ees ,eetoved
,ti evah nac yeht
tnuah taht noisiv reh ni segamiretfa rolocinhcet tuo gnivrac smra fo stes eerht eht ,ssorc taht otni serats ehs syaD
fo pord elgnis eht dna regnuh fo erutxim eht dna
.erif eht yb ti tes dna ti dehsols eH
.emit eht ta gnittimbus
.ytinasni gninevar
koot dna kool citehtapmys a reh evag retto ehT   ”.ecnis
.dnuob reverof dna gninrub reverof ydob naretporihc sih
t’nerA .oot reppus rof mih evah
.retfa yltrohs ecivres dna
”.niaga devol reven I
,tnelis saw retsam ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.dlrow elttil ruo ni enola tfel neeb evah dluoc ew kniht ot hsiloof saw tI
.pots ot meht htiw sdaelp ehS  ***  .ylluftiF
.erusserp tniaf a ylno
.stnallegalf dna stsidas fo tol a er’uoy kniht yehT
”.neht latrom demees eH .ti did I dna
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.retsis ,yrgnuh dekool uoY“
emac yllanif ehs taht ssorc-irt nori elttil a ,stsaerb reh neewteb tser ot hctam til A
,dehsiw eh gnihtynA
,reh ot ssenregae desserpxe eciov a ecnis gnol os neeb dah tI
.em dnimer ot deen t’nod uoY“ .dias eh
,yks eht tsniaga gnidnats
neeb dah aneyh eht naem ot ti koot tenniL dna
,nageb sthgin reh woh saw tahT   .gnihton
nun tibbar demra-eno ehT
,erutcip eht ta pu delims ylluS
.alliv elttil a ni nwot eht
.ti gninoitnem tuohtiw nwot otni rednaw reh tel
.egadnob yloh sih fo emuf gnicnad eht yb derucsbo etteuohlis sih
.nimrev htiw od ekam ot dah gnilgdelf ehT
.dekcilf rae s’tenniL   ”.tfel yeht dnA
”.daeh sih ekat dna oG“
.yad gnikaerb eht erofeb retlehs rof delf ehs dna ,detrap yehT
slaever riap elgnis yreve dna ,seye der thgirb sah meht fo eno elgnis yrevE
,oot ,ehS .ecaep dnuof eH
.yawa syaw trohs a elbat a no detser hcihw ,elttek a ot deltsub dna doots retto ehT
.elims hsiugor a htiw
,nam yhtlaew a t’nsaw rehtaf ym
ylpmis dah retsaM dna dnuorg retniw nezorf fo selim deklaw d’yehT .reh gnidiova erew elpoep rednow oN
.elbmert ot nageb swap s’tenniL retsiS ,seye telracs sih otni kcab dekool ehs sA
.nossel a saw sihT
.degduj tenniL ,tcepsa ’elam‘ fo boj eht rof tif doog ylbaugrani na
”?eye ruoy hctac gnihtemoS“
.sgnaf reh wohs t’ndid taht yaw a ni delims tenniL ”.stnallegalf
.ereht saw doG deR eht fo tseirp A“ .dias ylluS
.flow eht toN ”…eht gnirimda tsuj saw I ,yrros m’I“
.setirW_ijustihoK rednu
.yawa dekool tenniL retsiS dna
,tenniL denrut-ylwen ekilnU
.eow latrom fo ecneserp eht ni noitnetta ta tas reh ni rotaderp wen ehT
.daed eht gnoma raey a ylno saw tenniL retsiS
,eriter ot dediced yeht tsal ta nehW
lamina gniknihtnu na naht erom elttil semitemos si eripmav gnilgdelf A
.ti gnipleh on saw erehT
ll’ew dna ,enod er’uoy nehw rood eht yb mih evael tsuJ
.hsur laer on saw ereht dna
,tlep retniw suoicsul sih hguorht swap reh nur dluoc ehs woh dna ,evals dna ,feiht ,nahpro wollef reh ,etiK flow yarg eht ot derednaw dnim reH
shturt ,sgniht meht sllet ehS .gnihtyna od lliw ehs syas ehS .gnihtyna syas ehS
,mih htiw lla erofeb emac stluser tub
.seiceps eritne sih fo tcepsa elam fo evitatneserper ,flow cimetot a
,evol yna reh denrae reven feiht a sa efil remrof reH
.flow laref a erofeb doolb ni gnillor nwaf laref a ekil ,enecsbo saw tI .gnihton
,swodahs eht fo tuo gnikool retsaM eht sees ehs semitemoS
.snoitseuq gniksa dna srood no gnikconk saw ehs elihw
reven lliW .wonk tonnac
”,I dna ,sekahs elbirret eseht depoleved eh
tnetnoc fo noitamixorppa tnatsid reh ot deppis dna senips elttil rieht deppans ehS .yawyna meht thguac ehs tub
efil siht ni gnihton si erehT‘
.ti erudne ot denrael retsaM eht tuB
,niaga taeb ylraen traeh reH ”?tahw oG“
.ygolopa fo erutsop a ni srae reh dedlof dna tenniL retsiS diaS ”.hO“
,timmus niatnuom eht no gnidnats tsal ta mih tem nexiv ehT  .slamina
ot mih dlot etam tsrif eht -egaugnal eht ekops ylerab eH
,gnidliub eht morf nrot saw emoh sih gnidnefed cigam tneicna eht