.elzzum ynwat sih dessorc elims daorb a dna
.noil eht morf yawa secap wef a deppots dna
.gib taht noil a ot esolc gnitteg xof siht saw yaw oN
,llaw raf eht tsniaga gnidnats saw eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
emag eht ni retal erow oreh eht tes eht ot won ,emutsoc sih degnahc d’eH
.detrats noc eht erofeb syad tsuj dloc ytsan a htiw nwod emac sirhC nehw esrow tog sgnihT
”.thgirla eb ll’uoy dna nuf eb ll’tI
.emit elohw eht moor eht ni edih dna deracs teg t’noD
.ytiniffAruF dna yrruFoS no
.gab eht morf koobediug noc eht hguoht deppilf dna
”,ffeJ ,emit doog a evaH“
.noitingocer ekil dekool tahw
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.em dlot mussop eht
,peelsa llef I tniop emos tA
,yletilop dellac I ”!em esucxE“
.noitartsurf ni sserttam eht gnipmuht liat ym
.sreog noc eht fo tsom revo derewot eh
.emag-ni eno etirovaf ym s’tI
.saw eh eguh woh yb draug ffo thguac tsuj saw I—
tsenoh eb ot ,hcum ti eciton t’ndid I
,9 agaS ysatnaF ni tes romra etirovaf ym saw tI
emag eht fo did I hguorht yalp yreve no ti teg ot yaw ym fo tuo tnew I dna
,devas ,dennalp d’I
.selzzum rieht derevoc selims dna
”reyalpsoC noiL eht dna xoF ehT“
.durc noc rof oreZ tneitaP gnieb fo noitnetni on dah eh tub ,ti tuoba yrros repus saw eH
.srae ym ni esir tnemssarrabme fo taeh eht tlef I
,noc tsrif ym ta saw I—
,yaw ym denrut noil ehT
.dworc evissam eht ta derats I sa egdab ym teg ot enil ni saw I emit elohw eht nepo gnuh elzzum yM
.mih dniheb gnihsiws liat sih
.tae ot gnihtemos fo hcraes ni tuo dedaeh dna
,elpoep fo rebmun taht rof ydaer t’nsaw I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,tnemom a rof derats I
.em otni nur yllatnedicca ot elpoep rof gniksa sa doog sa saw teiuq dna llams gnieb—
.em ekil yug a er’uoy fi ecalp yracs a eb nac noitnevnoc A
.dehctiwt sreksihw dna srae
rehtegot flesym dellup ,dehgis I
.detanimod setoyoc dna—
depleh ti taht toN
.tsehc ym fo tuo gniremmah morf ti peek ot traeh ym ot wap a dleh dna llaw eht tsniaga denael I
.ecnavda ni moor letoh eht fo flah sih rof diap neve eh tniop eht ot detsisnI
.tnew ti no dna no dna ,noil a saw eh dna xof tik a saw I ,nwo ym no saw I
ym ni desserdrednu gnileef saw I taht emutsoc ni erew meht fo hguonE
,noitnevnoc reve tsrif ym eb ot gniog saw siht ecnis nwod em tog gniht elohw ehT
,yadretsey lenap ”noitnevnoC tsriF ruoY sI sihT oS“ eht ta denrael d’I tahw morF
”?erutcip a tog I fi yako eb ti dluoW
.delzzup ,deksa I ”?eM“
enoemos morf yawa nur d’I
htiw dehsalf seye siH
.sotohp ekat ot elpoep gnitivni saw eh
dna redluohs sih ffo gnihtemos dehsurb eH
.yawa deirrucs dna ciffart fo wolf eht deniojer I
”.uoy rof yllaicepsE“
”reyalpsoC noiL eht dna xoF ehT“:yojne esaelP
.sesucxe ekil tlef snosaer eht lla ,yb tnew sruoh eht sa tuB
.worromot sraef ym ecaf dna yrt ot gnivloser
ekatsim eno edam d’I tuB
.niaga mih ees t’ndluow I ebyam—noc gib a saw tI
.yawa thgir tset eht ot evloser ym tup gninrom ehT
sukcarD nedaJ yb
.dnim ym ni niaga revo dna revo noil eht htiw sretnuocne ym gninnur tpek I
.erofeb nosrep ni noil a nees reven d’I
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.sevlow fo elpuoc a htiw serutcip rof gnisop
.em ta nwod dekool dna denrut eH
?yracs taht yllaer eh saw
.daeh sih gnikahs ,tiftuo sih ta dekool
.yad eht fo lenap tsrif eht fo tuo deklaw I sa moor eht edistuo saw noil ehT
?noitnetta laiceps tirem ot enod I dah tahW
.gnihtemos gnittimda s’taht ,xof a rof dna—elbuort saw ti ,trohs nI
.em htiw emoc ot eerga ot sirhC dneirf ym nettog dna ,dehcraeser
,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy seirots erom roF
eht otni detsujda eh sa dias noil eht ”,haeY“
!eguh saw noil taht llits tuB
.llits saw liat sih dna ,elttil a demmuls erew sredluohs siH .saw eno on tuB
.enog saw eelf ot egru eht tub
.deneddas dna dennuts
tuo enohp ym dellup I
,9 agaS ysatnaF morf retcarahc niam eht sa pu desserd saw eH
yadretsey morf stsilenap eht tahw rebmemer ot deirt I sa gniwols liat ym
.og I taht detsisni dneirf ym tub
,gniliec eht ta gnirats deb eht no yal tsuj I—
.enola saw I ecno deppots yllanif I
.moor eht ot kcab tlob ot ydaer dna demlehwrevo saw I ,seidoog fo gab a dna egdab ym tog I emit eht yB
,GNAF ekil seigolohtna ni deraeppa sah krow esohw ,sukcarD nedaJ yb
,sukcarD nedaJ yb
.esruoc fo ,yaw taht tuo trats t’ndid tI
sexof ,reed ,sevloW
,dias eH ”!esruoc fO“
.gninrom eht ni 03:01 tuoba ylno saw ti dna noonretfa litnu no gniog hcum t’nsaw ereht ,yadirF a nO
.noc reve tsrif ym ta nwo ym no yllatot dna ,yhs
,noitcerid ym ni decnalg eH
.llits tnew liat nwo ym dna dewollaws I
.flesym fo demahsa saw I
.yracs dna eguh os saw eh tuB
,denruter sevren ehT
htiw tekcaj dna stnap kcalb kramedart s’retcarahc eht ni
si yrots s’yadot dna
.dias noil eht gnihtemos ta gnihgual sevlow eht was I tub
,dewols taebtraeh ym sa tuB
.dedne em edisni elttab eht dna
.etalp tsehc latemnug a dna mirt dlog htiw tiftuo nosmirc peed a—
.serutcip rof gniksa tuoba su dlot dah
.em ta sgnaf sih gnihsalf
thgin taht tpels ylerab I
.emag etirovaf ym fo tsinogatorp eht sa desserd
.stseretni emas eht fo tol a sah ereht enoyreve—rebmemer dnA“
,yadretsey ot gnitnaw elpoep fo ytnelp dah d’eH
.dnuora noitnevnoc gnimag/emina/if-ics tseggib eht ,noCekarD ot gniog ot otni em klat sdneirf ym tel I—
.etalp tsehc etihw dna dlog
?mih htiw serutcip gnikat eno on saw yhW
elttil a kcab egaruoc ym tog I ,noitartsiger dnuora dworc evissam eht morf yawA
.rodirroc eht nwod dna
.emosewa saw romra taht dna
.efil ym ni erofeb enoyna fo denethgirf os neeb reven d’I
”.yadretsey gniraew erew uoy trihs looc taht tog uoy erehw ksa ot detnaw I“
.otni depmub teg t’ndluow I os elbissop sa llams sa flesym gnikam elihw cinap ton ot tseb ym did dna
.emutsoc ruoy evol I“
.onrufnI ehT dna ,taeH
.ereht eb dluow em htiw stseretni derahs taht elpoep rehto ynam woh tsuj noitnem ot togrof eH
”reyalpsoC noiL eht dna xoF ehT“ saw sihT
ym dna mih dezingocer I sa esnet tnew ydob yM
.ti otni troffe fo tol a tup d’eH
pets a ekat ot egru eht thguof I .denruter seirrow ym sa llef srae yM
.ytinutroppo siht pu ssap ot gniog saw I yaw on saw ereht—
.rodirroc eht ssorca em gniyrrac ydaerla erew swap ym ,noitanimreted suovren ni gnihsiws saw liat ym dna pu tnew srae ym emit eht yB
,em dellif tlob ot egru ehT
xof tik rehto eno was ylno I hguoht—
,mih htiw emit doog a gnivah erew elpoep fi tuB
.ydaer tsomla ,lleW
roivaheb ym ezilanoitar ot deirt I tsrif tA
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.rodirroc eht ni ciffart gninrom ylrae rethgil eht gnihctaw dna llaw eht tsniaga gnidnats saw eh elihW .ti ni doog dekool noil eht dnA
.epoh nrolrof a saw ti denrael I
.etisoppo eht devresed I ,em deciton yllaer neve d’eh fI
.mih was I nehw s’tahT
.tsrif ta noisiced suoicsnoc a gnikam rebmemer t’nod I
?tsafkaerb emos teg dna og dluohs I ebyaM
,llams er’uoy fi yllaicepsE
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
em deracs dna em naht reggib saw eh taht rettam t’ndid tI
,mih sa gib sa enoyna nees reven d’I
renroc eht dnuora detrad I erofeb was I lla saw tahT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.kcaskcab gnirtsward dna snaej dna trihs-t ”xoF remyaG“
,meht dniheb gnihsiws erew sliat s’enoyrevE
.kcolnu ot stseuq edis fo seires gnol ylgnizinoga na deriuqer ti hguoht neve—
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro
,retal sruoh eerht ned srelaed eht gnivaeL
,degnahc noisserpxe sih nehT .kcab
.esop yrotciv agaS ysatnaF