,ti etaicerppa I
”?dnim ruoy no cificeps gnihtemos saW
’.hctilg a eb tsum
,erusserp eht nrut dluoc I neht
.ereh era ew yhw uoy llet ton deen I kniht I“
”?siht lla wonk uoy od woh oS ?yakO“
,rorrim eht tsniaga ni denael eh
”?naem uoy od tahW“
,dlo otni gniknis tub
,emit ym htiw eveihca I tahw ,tnerruc eht esaercni I fi ,oS
”.tset eht rof kcul dooG
”.uoy knahT“ .derac eh fi sa
.detpecca dna thguoht eH
.krow si ygrene taht
,sdnah sih gnivaw saw regnarts ehT
.mih fo retteb eht teg ot gniyrt cinap dna suovren
”.luos ym stcetorp ohw uoy si ti won
dlrow eht dedaoler eH
,flesym ti dnatsrednu tey t’nod I ,tsenoh eb oT“
.tfel ydobyreve elihw yats ot noediG deksa ehS
.swollag eht ot dehcram eh yadseuT nO
,gnitrofmoc dna gnimraw noitome nA
.niaga gnuoy gnileef - snoitasnes dnof
.on ,fpmH“ ”?thgirla uoy era
,ereht erew sliame deteled ehT
”.gnihtemos fo em sdnimer tI
ssenitpme dloc eht ylno gnitcepxe
sthguoht mih gnirepsihw
ffo tesdaeh sih koot eh llit emit fo tnuoma nwonknu na mih koot tI
.gnol ekat t’ndluohs tI
.knalb saw dnim sih
,sdnalsi gnitaolf detisiv eh
lla ti tuoba tegrof ot gnitnaW
dna ereht ecnereffid a edam
,rorrim eht fo edis rehto eht no noinapmoc detcepxenu na dnuof dna
.egap emas eht no ton ylpmis erew owt uoy ,oN“ ”.gnorw saw I oS
,yaw taht ti tuoba thguoht t’nevah I“ .deksa natrapS ”?won anosruf wen ruoy si siht oS
.mih ta kcab gnikool seye tohsdoolb ,derit
.elpmaxe rof ,naf a fo noitator eht eb nac sihT
”.gniklat erew ew elihw flesym tuoba gnihtemos denrael I kniht I
;erutcip eht ni saw eh erehT
,setunim wef a ylno saw tI“
,niaga ffo daeh ot evah I ,yldaS
:tib eno siht em eveileb ,llitS
.ti tup ot yaw gnitseretni
noediG desserdda OEC ehT
.thgir scisab eht hcaet t’ndid yeht ekil sdnuos tI“
noitanigami dna maerdyad ot nageb eH
.rehtegot ylimaf eht gnipeek eno eht saw eh taht
…enod I evah tahW“
I‘ .mih nopu denwad ti litnu nwod dna pu sunem sih dehcraes eh yllacitnarF
”.oot ,srehto rof ereht eb nac I
.elprup dna der ,eulb fo euh a ni detnit saw ytic ehT
”rorriM eht fo ediS rehtO ehT“
.wohs VT eht dekil noediG hcum woh wenk eh esuaceb
,lliw ta erusserp eht ,egatlov eht egnahc tonnac uoy ,regnarts taht ot denialpxe I sA .noitcnuf ot sceps niatrec ot tliub si metsys a
.kcohs ni saw eH ”.dennab era uoY“
,retupmoc sih ot tnew eh tibah fo tuO
.noitanalpxe elpmis siht ni yal hturt repeed a taht gnileef a dah eH
.tsehc nedoow eht ni saw tahw
.daer dna nwod tas noediG
?oot ,evlove ebyam eh dluoC
.eb nac taht drah woh wonk osla I tub
.deen fo semit ni pleh ot dna
”.eugnot ym fo pit eht no gnittis s’ti leef I
dlrow a ni flesmih dnuof eh
,deirrac ti epoh eht
.dias natrapS ”.noediG yeH“
dnuos si nalp ruoY
.peels emos teg ot deganam eh yllautnevE
.tnereffid tlef eh nehw emit a morf
”?rettam siht no yas ot gnihtyna evah uoy oD“
nos sih dnuora mra na ,mih ot txeN
deirrac ssenismulc siht taht emahs eht
”-neht dna ,erusserp hcum os
”?detsixe reven uoy dnif ot pu ekaw I lliW
.tlef ti woh ot bmun ylno yllaer tub
.ti devas yletaidemmi eh
,mH“ ”?noitulove na ti llac dluohs I ebyam oS
,niaga fles dlo sih ekil tlef deedni eh taht pleh ton did tI
,ti dnuof I nehw deticxe os saw I
,rehtegot tpek taht ylimaf a fo trap dna
.uoy stius yllaer fles wen ruoy
.nuf erom neve saw gnippoh dlrow
.tnemom a rof tnelis saw natrapS
.ereht llits erew smaerd dna
.lleb a fo noediG dednimer daeh esohw
.reh pleh ot deirt I esruoC“ ”?melborp reh ot noitulos a dnif reh pleh ot yrt uoy did ro reh ot netsil tsuj uoy did ,lleW“
.hguoht ,morf semoc ti erehw wonk t’nod I .negotorp
sratava flow htiw
,esuap degnolorp a saw erehT
.ti denepo eh sa mih tem ria hserf fo tsalb A
.rorrim eht ot esolc delwarc eH
,mih dnuora deraeppa dlrow emoh siH
…uoy rof kool tub gnihton did I
,yawa dessap dah rehtaf sih retfa sraey ynaM .rehtaf etal sih
”.si ti kniht I ,sey tub
,thguoht eh ’…ega ym fo nam a rof yllis os si
yb welf ruof egap ,eerht egaP
ot deen dluow I thguoht I
,teef sih ta yal sdlrow fo sdnasuohT
”.ma I ereh llits tub ,tey deraperp t’nevah dna worromot tset a tog ev’I
,detivni dah eh sdneirf desoppus eht lla fo tuO
.niav ni gnitiaw mih tfel neve dna deil
,lufsserts saw tI
.yenruoj siht morf denruter eh erofeb
”.uoy fo negotorp os deedni si
,sevlesmeht fo noisrev retteb dna lufrewop erom a otni
tiaw saw did eh lla ,dneirf gniyd a fo edisdeb eht ta gnittis ekiL
esuoh-ni selosnoc nur detimil eht tiforter ot
.tahw s’tahw teg t’nod dna
.mih ta delims negotorp sih
.dneirf sih rof devas eh taht setadidnac doog owt dnuof dna tuo meht deirt noediG
,ksed sih ta nwod gnittis fo daetsnI
.ygrene ,rewop otni
,sdneirf eb dluoc sgnieb ekilnu hcus woH
.yad taht fo pukcab eht dekcehc noediG
.meht fo emaceb tahw yas ton dluoc tub
?niaga mih dnif ton dluow eh fi tahW :derednow noediG
.sratava dnif ot syaw rof tenretnI eht dehcraes eH
,deirram si enim fo dneirf A ?ecneirepxe efiL“
,ereh gnorw ro thgir on s’erehT
.nihtiw ecnedifnoc gniworg a ,dewener tlef eH
,smelbme tnereffid htiw negotorP hsiulb ,hsiddeR
.enog gnol emit htiw dekaos saw repap eht fi sa
.noon fo yhs tsuj saw ti ,yad txen eht ekow eh nehW  2 fo
”.erus ma I ,revo si sisirc siht nehw os od lliw I tub
.hcraes ratava na gnidulcni ,snoitpo wen htiw decnahne neercs unem eht
tI‘ .ereht ton saw ratava ehT
.srehto rof dna sevlesmeht rof
ecnadiug reffo ot
yllaer uoY .tpurretni ot tnaw ton did dna yug taht gnipleh uoy waS
:yojne esaelP  .smaerd sih otni
,dehsinav natrapS drow rehtona tuohtiW
.evol dluow natrapS erus saw eh
.uoy stius ti kniht I ,tsenoh eb oT“
”.em rof saw ydobyna yldrah taht srehto rof nosrep eht eb em pleh esaelP
.tib a erolpxe dna daeha og lliw I
,noitcelfer sih tsniaga ni denael eh ,gnileenK
.ttub ym devas evah yam uoy
”.ti dedeen eh yaw eht level eye no
.spets sih ecarter ot deirt eh os
,noitacifidom eht fo secart lla devomer dah eh ecnO
t’nod I .rae ym ffo wehc reh gnittel ruoh na tneps tsuJ
.teltuo na sa krow fo edistuo efil ym htiw gnihtemos gniod ;evitcudorp
.eurt morf raf s’taht yas ot sseldeen tub ,modnaF eht ni ecalp erom on evah sruf redlo ew taht kniht
sklof emos ebyaM
,kool yam ti yllis woh fo thguoht yna gniwolla toN
.nwod erew senohp PI eht dna
”.hturt eht morf mih dedleihs ytilaer fo thgil eht gnikaerb sesnel eht dna
ees ot fles eurt ym tub ,esle gnihtoN
”?taht tuoba laiceps os si tahW .teem ot deneppah I yug a pleh ot emit fo tib a koot tsuj I
.seye nwo sih otni pu dekool eH
.won evael tsuj ot thgir leef ton did tI
.reward a nepo dellup dna
,ecaf lautca sih ees dluoc eh
”.niaga dom a esu reven dna tneilc ym erotser lliw I ,enif eb lliw tI
.decafrus oga gnol yadhtrib a fo seiromeM
.sliam-e dna tnemucod eht hguorht daer dna
.llac a edam eh dna ,demrof nalp A
.derolpxe eb ot ydaer
,huH“ .dnim s’noediG hguorht dehsur dias tsuj natrapS tahW ”.nomigiD ,neht kcab devol uoy wohs VT dlo tahT“ ”?ti si tahW ?hO“
,regnuoy elttil a erew I ylno fI“ .elims ot dah eh
,ffP“ ”?negotorp a fo taht ksa uoY“
.yadot hteet dewohs uoy woh ees ot dalg ma I timda ot evah I ,dias tahT
deitpme nibac eht dna
.taht uoy yned ot I ma ohw
tnerruc ro etar wolf eht
nosaer on ees I suht ,krow lliw ti erus ma I dna
.ezorf dlrow eht tnemom tahT .derepsihw eH
.dlrow siht otni dekcus tog eh hcum woh
.krow si ygrenE :siht rebmemer
.modnaF ehT“ ”?tahw tuobA“
terces ni tem lla yeht yad txen ehT
,eurt eb ot pihsdneirf fo egami siht rof dehsiw syawla I“
,edis rehto eht no seye eht ni yhtapmys ees ot deveileb tsomla dna pu dekool eH
ratava sih fo eman eht derebmemer noediG
,won sneppah tahw rettam oN“
,gninrut fo tnemevom eht
”?uoy yllaer taht sI ?noediG“
gnieb eb thgim ti neht
,od dluoc eh esle gnihton saw erehT .deb ot tnew eH
,gnihton rof trepxe na ton era uoY
.efil hguorht htap ym no em htiw ereht syawla erew uoY
,VT no was eh serutaerc eseht tuoba
.detnioppasid dna deyarteb
,romra gnikool if-ics neerg ni nam ralucsum ylrevo dna llat A
,no won morf tub ,wonk t’nod I
,elpoep yb dednuorrus dna
.zzaj taht lla dna tnerruc ,egatlov dnuora daeh ym parw t’nac I
.tseuqer s’natrapS derebmemer dna reffo no
tsuj s’doog tahW .reh evol I
saw ereht tsehc sih ni teY
,sliops eht gnirahs ,yako ,yakO“
.ratava negotorp sih otni kcab egnahc ot detnaw noediG
,deyonna dna derit
,sbmoluoc dna seluoj ot thgir depmuj eW
”.suoiruc ma I won ,lleW“
.gnittes saw nus ehT
”.reh rof gniyduts ffo tup I dna
,yeh tub ,em staeB“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
ylluferac dekool eH
.nwod mih dehsup dna traeh sih ta erot taht
.tnegru si ti tub ,yadnuS a no uoy brutsid ot yrros ,haraS ,yeH“
noitanalpxe deliated erom a regnarts eht evig ot no tnew noediG
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.reffo ot tol a ev’ew kniht I
.degnahc gnihton taht ;flesym deloof I taht ,eil a si ereh siht lla taht won diarfa ma I“
,rorrim eno tsael ta deniatnoc ereh dlrow yrevE
.natrapS ot gniklat eulB raeh dluoc noediG
,nwo sih detniap eh savnac eht saw ratava ehT
,fles dlo ym ot kcab og t’now I
,rorrim eht fo tnorf ni doots dna pu tog noediG gninrom txen ehT
.gniteem eht denepo OEC ehT
tsom derimda eh tcepsa ehT
”.emit lluf gnikrow fo enituor tluda eht otni tog I ecno erusserp eht esae
.sthguoht fo liart sih ni deppots noediG
.margorp elosnoc emag ruo dereenoip dna rehtaf ym rednu ereh dekrow ydaerla uoY
,wolf retaw ekam ot nrut ot sah pmup retaw a ekil tsuJ
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     ”.uoy si
.kcab gnilims negotorp eht
.dlrow eht ni tsurt cisab a dna
.nomigiD dellac wohs a was dna
,peY“ .dehgual noediG
mih ta elims ot demees negotorp eht dna ,debbos eH
htaerb peed a koot eh oS
.mih no nwad ot nageb ti nehT
.mih tih ytilaer dna ekorb dleihs s’rehpargotohp eht taht neht
- mih ot ti detfig tsrif dad sih nehw
?neppah ti did nehW“
secaps desolcne ni meht tup elpoep esuaceb ,ffo gnirewop era selosnoc ehT
.reganam ruoy rof tpecxe
”?ecalp tsrif eht ni siht ekil ti nialpxe yeht t’nod yhW
,uoy sekil maet ruoy
.ereht gnidnats dneirf sih was dna dnuora denrut noediG
.dlrow laer eht ni naht ereh erom devil eh syad wef tsal ehT
m’I dna ,esnes elttil ekam salumrof ehT
mih ot ti denialpxe uoy dna egdelwonk eht sah ydobyreve ton esuaceb ,si tI“
,dnim sih dessorc thguoht gnirad a dna
tsal yam I gnol revewoh ot gninnigeb eht morF spetstoof fo liart a evael dnA
,etarepsed dna nevirD
.snoitome dna seiromem nettogrof meht htiw dna
,mrE“ ”?dah ehs melborp a tuoba uoy llet ehs did
rae na reffo llew sa thgim eh thguoht noediG
.stsoc tuc ot tinu gnilooc evitca eht evomer ot em detcurtsni uoy ,riS“
noitadnuof eht era uoY
”.netsil ot syap ti dna
sepoh eht lla ,seulav eht llA
erif gnildnik a ekiL
.noitcelfer sih dialrevo
saw ti dna ,gniyd ro daed erew sesroh roop ehT .ria eht ni yal
,nam ,zeeJ .ti teg I ,thgirla ,thgirlA“
.em tsuj ma I ,niaga neht tub ,dneirf dlo na ot lleweraf gniddib ekiL .drieW“
sdlrow fo tsil eht nO
.ereht olleh …lleW“
,siht lla gniksir I mA
?ebuTuoY no lennahc nwo ruoy evah ebyaM
wonk ot deen I lla
.emoh ym ni ylno saw I dna
”.uoy tsol I thguoht I .dog knahT“
”.kcab uoy evah ot doog ,yeH“
”.llud dna yrd os lla s’tI
.launam eht ni ecivda eht tsniaga
,llew secaf eht lla wenk eH
,hcum os sknaht ,nam yeH .yako ,lol
sihT‘ .ffo deggol eh dna gninrom eht ni ruof saw tI
.no fles neddih ecno
”.kniht em edam yadretsey klat ruo ,yeh tuB
”?gniklat er’ew yhw s’taht thguoht I“
,rehto hcae rof evarb dna layol eb
devas dah eh llA
.kcab derats ylevissap negotorp eht
.uoy deteerg I nehw naeco eht otno tuo gnikool erew uoY“
htiw yticirtcele fo scisyhp laer eht ot detaler ygolana retaw siht woh fo
.hcraes ratava na elbane ot noitacifidom tneilc a gnillatsni dednemmocer taht tsop enil-no na ssorca emac eh tniop emos tA
,edutilos ot desu nettog ton dah eh ebyam taht thguoht deedni eH
.egatlov si retaw eht fo erusserp eht dna
?epoh siht esol eh did nehW .gnikniht
.psarg ot gniyrt saw eh taht hturt siht rof hsif sthguoht sih tel eh
ygrene evitisop emos sdeen modnaF eht ,yeh tub
”.hguoht ,tnereffid taht leef ton did I .yddub ,sknaht
sroolf rieht no ffo tog srobhgien sih eno yb enO
”.yawyna ,won gnikniht emos od dluohs I ,yako s’ti dna
,lamron saw siht fi derednow eH
.traeh sih no saw tahw sdrow otni tup ot gniyrt ylniav gnieb siht ot gniklat ekil tlef eH
,sdrow retteb otni ti tup t’nac I taht yrros ,lleW
erutseg a htiw ffo mih tuc OEC eht tub
,emoh lautriv sih ni
.rorrim eht fo edis rehto eht morf erutaerc siht gnicarbme fo noitom eht edam eh
,OEC eht moor gniteem gib eht nI
.ytniatrec htiw yaw taht eb nac I
.nac ew taht syaw llams eht ni rehto hcae depleh
lasoporp siht ot noitidda ni dna dias noediG
.thguoht eH ’.togrof I taht
”.ti fo tser eht wonk ot tnaw I won ,no oG
.snottub eht yb ecalp sih koot eh sa
;pu meht gnitfil yb
.noitpecxe on saw siht dna
;uoy tcetorp ot detnaw I ecnO
daer saw skoob cimoc fo elip a ;dessap sruoH
.tnemom a rof gnikniht ,mih deppots yug llat eht litnu
.gnilims saw dneirf sih teb eh rof
’.yadot dneirf a edam I
.enola saw eh litnu
”.noitanalpxe na deen eW“
,won dezilaer noediG sA
,gniliaf era elosnoc wen ruo fo snoitide detimil ehT
?tneitapmi os I saw yhW
.mih eulav I hcum woh natrapS dewohs syawla I ,yllufepoH
.esnes sekam tI
,arDiK yb ”rorriM eht fo ediS rehtO ehT“
.secaf tnereffid eht gniziromem
.emoh tnew noediG revo saw yadkrow eht retfA
,ssalg eht tsniaga desiar smra
.dehgis dna roolf eht no tas noediG
.niaga evila leef yllanif dluow I kniht I
.uoy htiw elbarenluv gnieb elbatrofmoc leef dna uoy htiw snoitome reh erahs ot detnaw ehs taht tub
.eno tsal eht saw evif dna
,seno ynit ,seno ylliS
,negotorp eht dnuof dah eh taht dlrow cilbup a ni saw tI
.dlrow eht morf dih dna semit ynam oot eno truh tog uoY
tesdaeh eht hguorhT ”?tahw ekiL“
:pu deppop egassem A
”?siht no tupni ym tnaw uoy od ,lleW .uoy teg I
enil rewop eht hguorht swolf taht ygrene otni
.noitcelfer sih htiw daeherof ot daeherof
,troppus ruoy htiW
.noitacifidom eht dellatsni dna
.yawa thgir smelborp ot snoitulos dnif ot tnaw dna
.layarteb ekil tlef dah
,haey tub ,taht rof yrroS
”?uoy dnif ot tiaw ton dluoc I esuaceb ,uoy gniksir
,retsaf dellorcs noediG .owt egap no ton
…gnihtemos otno eb thgim uoy kniht I ,wonk uoY“
efil rieht ni nomed a dah ydobyreve ton fi derednow dna daer eH
.delims dna rorrim eht dehcuot eH
.tesdaeh RV sih rednu morf nwod nar sraet dna
,ynapmoc siht ot eeyolpme na tsuj ton era uoY
?ti t’nsaw ,uoy rof hcum oot saw tI .deid dad nehT“
.gnihcaet uoy ees nac I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.rehpargotohp a saw meht fo enO
?em gnipleh uoy era yhw tub
,worromot tset a evah I
,stroffe sih etipseD
.em deen sdik eht tub
fo     trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadot dna
foor eht ot gnidael
.retupmoc sih ot dehsur noediG ”…pukcab yM“
,pot eht ot yaw eht lla ,pu rehgiH
.skoob cimoc dlo sih fo thgis railimaf eht dnuof eh ,edisnI
tsuj lla ew fi ecalp retteb a eb dluow dlrow eht esuaceB“
.hguoht ,won evael dluohs I
,enips sih pu depeerc llihc A
,ereht llits saw ti
.esahp suoilleber sih retne ot tuoba yob a tsuj
,ezilaer ot tnemom a mih koot tI .gnihtemos
.gnittes nus eht htiw krad gnitteg saw moor ehT
,nageb esrevinu eht ssorca esahc A
.noitcelfer sih dlot eh ”.enif eb lliw tI“
?ti saw dlrow tahw
,gnihtemos yas ot tuoba saw eh ekil dekool
”.senildaeh eht gnikam si swen evitagen dna
,enim gnidulcni ,smaet llA
.negotorp a sa flesmih was eh nehw tlef eh taht noitome emas eht saw ti
,ygolana nwo sih tuoba thguoht noediG
,natrapS morf siht raeh ot doog tlef tI
llewriats eht debmilc eh roolf pot eht nO
epoh eht ni sdlrow depmuj eh sruoh erom ynam rof dna
”.yadot llew did I kniht uoy fi
.efil ni rof dehsiw syawla dah eh taht lla saw ti
,mH“ ”?noitulos a ot dael t’nseod ti nehw gniklat
,won ereh siht gniod tub
”?niaga reve uoy truh dluoc ydobon os yawa uoy edih I did rO
,ygrene teg ot dna
.yug taht ot denialpxe tsuj I tahw tuoba gnikniht neeb ev’I“
,oS .epip eht fo retemaid eht si
noitatiseh rehtruf tuohtiw dna
.maet gnireenigne eht yb desuac tluaf lacinhcet a tuoba gniklat era eW“
.loohcshgih morf otohp ssalc a saw enO .did eh emit siht tub
,gnizama ,taerg hO“
htaed fo hcnets eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
gniliar eht otno denael eH
.enog ton saw dlrow lautriv siht ni rorrim eht ni dekool eh nehw dah eh gnileef eht tub
”.gnikniht fo syaw tnereffid tsuj
.revo eb ot ti detnaw eH
?yadnoM no ylrae rehtegot sdael maet rehto eht teg uoy naC
…ratava eht devas reven
,kcab emac nettogrof dah eh sliated eht lla no daer eh sA
,temleh a gniraew
,mih ot tnaem ti tahw fo gnidnatsrednu wen a htiw ni gnikooL
.ksed sih ot txen flehs a no sotohp eht ta dekool eh ,daetsnI
.troppus rof gnikool
,tiderc emos flesruoy evig os ,oot ,uoy morf tol
”?reh rof od ot detnaw uoy tahw ees t’ndluoc ehs ebyaM
,traeh sih nihtiw eb yam ereht revetahw ot denetsil dna
”!em ot netsil reven uoY“
,rorrim eht tsniaga ni denael eH
,enin retpahc dehcaer eh nehW
.esiwrehto hcum gniod ton yb nwod flesym tel I woh ees I woN
,sliat yffulf htiw emos
dna nwod kcik reven uoY
rorrim eht nI .daol desserp eH
raelc yllufniap emaceb ti
,nehT .slias ym ni dniw eht erew uoy dna
”?kniht uoy od tahw ,oS
,gnorw tlef tneilc eht gniyfidom fo thguoht ehT
,krow refsnart eW
.taolfa em tpek uoY .boj tsrif ym
.mih brutsid dluow ydobon erehw ecnatsni etavirp a otni
”.ylgnidrocca eussi eht htiw laed lliw I
”?yawa uoy kcol I did rO
gnignoleb dna evol ,efil fo erutan eht serolpxe ohw ,arDiK yb
.nwod meht tup dna sklof regnuoy nopu nwod kool ton dluohs seno redlo eW
.htgnerts dna mlac fo ecruos a
;em nihtiw syawla erew uoy ,won ti ees I“
.uoy llet ll’I rebmemer I fI“
,roolf ht41 eht rof nottub eht sserp ot detnaw noediG
”.gniogtuo os gnieb uoy ees ot dalg ma I ,yltsenoh
V serutnevdA nomigiD saw tI
.flesti efil ot eurt saw taht gnihtemos neve ebyaM
,yad yreve ecaf ot evah ylpmis stluda sa ew taht
”.oot ,uoy ees ot doog s’tI
.lativ dna raed gnihtemos tsol ydaerla eh tlef eh tub
.mih dnuof yllanif eh thguoht dna
sddo eht dehgiew eh
”.toidi ydoolb a ekil ereh gnidnats em evael tsuj
.enilffo og ot ekawa dna
.won elihw a rof kcab m’I ,haeY“
,kooL .yako ,dog ha …lleW“
yticirtcele fo stnemele eht htiw efil tluda gninialpxe taht uoy llet em tel tuB
.seipoc edam dna lasoporp a pu etorw noediG
.ytilaer gnidnuorrus eht htiw gnipoc emit drah a dah sreidlos gnuoy ehT
”.fo em dednimer ratava ruoy tahw derebmemer I taht
”…flesym nomed taht thgif dluoc I
emitrevo yratnulov od ot deerga
.siht rof dennab teg dluoc eh ;derevihs eh dna
,os kniht uoy fi ,lleW“
,esruoc fO“ ”?ruoh na flah
.mih nihtiw esor cinap
,snwot lanoitidart
yadot yug taht gnipleH
.mih denioj dna enilno emac natrapS
,tuoba dekool eh gnidnecsa elihW
.niaga no deggol eh
,sratava devas sih htiw lenap eht denepo eh nehW
.tinu gnilooc eht peek ot snoitadnemmocer sih gnidirrevo reganam sih morf sliam-e eht fo ypoc a enola OEC eht dednah
,ereht ysae ,mrE“ ”.no
ydobemos saw syawla erehT
.tnemom a rof thguoht noediG
,niaga mih esol ton ot regaE
,em htiw uoy evah I sa gnol sa
stinu eht pu xim I .ti fo ekas eht rof traeh yb ffuts gninrael tsuj ta doog ton
”.uoy htiw snoitome reh erahs ot tnatropmi erom neeb evah yam ti reh oT .thgiR“
,diputs os dnuos tsum sihT“ .daeh sih koohs noediG
.tey wonk t’nod I“
,sesucxe pu edam emoS .pu dewohs enon
.seulav dna sepoh ym
”.eno siht ot noitcennoc a leef I tub
.deksa reganam siH
.tinu a hcus esuoh ot tliub dna
,ydaerla detseb ew selcatsbo emocrevo
”?uoy ot yticirtcele gnihtyreve si
reganam snoediG
,retaw fo tnuoma eht si egrahc fo tnuoma ehT .epip a ot detcennoc knat retaw a enigamI .haeY“ ”?won ti sI“ ”.si yticirtcele tahw dnatsrednu uoy ecno ysae s’tI
?yllaer …tiaw ,tiaw ,tiaW“ ”.pmup retaw a ekil
”?tahw ,hE“ ”?thgirla uoy ,yeH“
,nwod mih gnihgiew ssendas dna tbuod eht tuohtiW
.naem uoy tahw won ees nac I ,tsalb hO
.niav ni saw hcraes ehT
.em rof hcum oot rO
.stinu esoht dniheb gnitteg tuohtiw dnoces eno rof pma eno ekil gnieb
ekatsim a sa siht tniap ew stseggus gnitekraM
.deveiler tlef noediG ”.doog sdnuoS“
srewsna dna snoitseuq htiw htrof dna kcab tnew yehT
.efil sih morf evomer ot dah eh emos dna
,mH“ .mih ot denialpxe ecno natrapS gnihtemos
.diputs dnuos t’nseod ti ,oN“
siht sa rorrim eht ni flesym was I tlef I“
,noitautis eht xif ot lasoporp a evah ew dna sdael maet rehto eht ot deklat I
.dniheb evael dluow eil a taht
.dekcehc I tsal ,lleW“
.traeh sih ffo gnillaf
si rotareneg a
,eno egap no ton saw negotorp siH
.niaga fles xof dlo sih emaceb eh oS
,tey ’boj doog‘ uoy llet tonnac I
,niaga ti ees I .seY“
.raef laitnetsixe siht dehs ton dluoc eh ,llitS
.spets sih gnicarter ,efil hguorht htap sih llacer ot deirt eh
a denrael I .nac ew revenehw dnah gnipleh a reffo
,rorrim eht fo edis rehto eht no
,hguoht ,uoy llet ot detnaw I
rehtona retfa enO
.truh teg regnol on ot ,yawa uoy dih I
.tihs siht em sevig syawla dna dneirflrig ym s’ehS
eciffo emoh ni dekrow eh yad eht derebmemer eh sa sniev sih hguorht gnihsur doolb draeh eH
niaga ecno fo gnileef A
eb ot tnaw I ohw eb lliw I neht dnA
.no gniog repeed gnihtemos saw ereht tlef eh teY
”.ynapmoc siht evas lliw ew ,seY .nalp a evah I
raed dloh dna rebmemer lliw I
seiromem kcab thguorb otohp ylimaf ehT
”.siht lla gniod era ew yhw s’tahT
.regnarts eht dehcaorppa
.retal stnemom dehsinav ehS
2 traP ,arDiK yb
meht pleh dluohs ew leef I ,daetsnI
.srettam taht lla s’taht nehT“
,gnineve yadirF a no krow morf emoh emac noediG ,emit tsaL
?ebyam ,doohdlihc fo dne larutan ehT
.won esnes erom hcum os sekam ti ,kceh eht tahW“
”.dratsab uoy ,won uoy tog I“ .gnimrof elims a
,sneercs gnidaol eht ni snoitacifidom hcus tuoba sgninraw erew erehT .suoregnad
,naeco eht otno tuo gnikooL
”rorriM eht fo ediS rehtO ehT“
dneirf esolc a htiw saw eh ,yadretseY
.tnemeerga na ot emac dna
”.uoy esol ot tnaw t’nod I …oN“
ni gniggol retfA
,gninnigeb eht ni eh saw erehW
.skrow evitaerc ynam dna semag citsirutuf
.raehrevo ot ton drah saw ti
,erew uoy ,em tsurT“
”.hturt eht dna mih neewteb ni dnats regnol on dluoc aremac siH
?reh htiw noitulos a no krow ot deirt dna
sseuG‘    .mih morf tseuqer dneirf a deviecer noediG
ecalp eno taht dnif ot
,gniwolf si retaw eht nehW
aremac sih hguorht dlrow eht ta dekool ylno eH
niaga negotorp taht ees ot detnaw noediG .sedaced ni
”?rehtruf tib a taht nialpxe uoy naC
’.mih dnif ot evah I
reh pleh ot detnaw uoY
”.retemarap gnorw eht gnitsujda saw I ees I
”?eb taht dluow tahW ?yllaeR“
VT dehctaw eh yad enO
ot deirt I tibah fo tuo esuaceb
tnelis saw natrapS
.dlrow lautriv eht otni kcab teg ot ystna tlef dna
.nwod tis ton did emit siht tub
”?noitcennoc fo tros tahW“
”?gnol os rof erew uoy xof eht eb regnol on ot leef ti seod woH
.deteled retal eh taht liame aiv snoitcurtsni mih tnes dah reganam siH
.netfo erom pu kcik esaelp tub
neht kcab dna netfo truh tog I
deretlehs gnieb fo gnileef ehT
,efil ym ot deilppa
”?tuoba siht si tahW“
.noitcnuf ecived a evah llits dna
.kool wen sih dekil natrapS dalg saw eH
.gnihtemos dekoolrevo dah eh ebyaM
?gnivlove ydaerla eh saW
,dnoyeb yal tahw gnidih ecnatsid eht ni ezah eht
.gnidaer ekil ,gniht eno no sruoh rof sucof ot tluciffid saw ti yllausU
.retteb snetsil ohw ydobemos teg uoy erus ekam lliw I
,ytisrevinu dednetta I
.won tnereffid sgniht wef a ees I kcab gnikool dna sedaced rof ereh neeb ev’eW
.enola erom ecno saw noediG dna
,lufetarg yllaer m’I ,kooL“
si ereht lla roF
.daol ot tneilc eht rof gnol ekat ton did tI
”.yaw taht leef em edam ylniatrec
evlove dluoc yeht troffe taerg htiw taht saw ,nomigiD eht
.txen eht ta dekool dna
dehsiw noediG ecno siht dna
”.ypoc a ekat hcae dna gnola eseht ssap esaelP
...esnes ekam seod tahT“
.rood yvaeh eht denepo dna
.erusaelp ym saw ti dna ,aedi dooG“
ytilaer lautriv ni yenruoj a no tnew eh
nwod gum sih tup eH
.yadot dlob yllausunu neeb dah eH
pu emac stluser hcraes ehT .ni ti depyt dna
,tnangats leef ot nageb efil ym kniht I“
.wolf snortcele ekam ot nrut ot sah rotareneg a
.tib a rednop ot ecalp thgir eht ekil tlef tI
tsap ym ni doog eht lla
,unem elbisivni eht gnikrow
,yddub yrroS .remmub ,hO“
.tnemtrapa sih ni enola
,renilcer sih ni tas eh
.seussi htiw em ot emoc syawla nac uoy wonk uoy taht ,em ot tnatropmi si tI
drager taht ni tnereffid eb ot dnet nem eW
,rorrim eht ni dekool eH
.yawyna demood ma I“
negotorp sih rof ksir on gnikaT
.rorrim eht etisoppo llaw eht tsniaga derewoc
.noitasrevnoc eht deunitnoc dneirf sih ,ylikcuL
.noitadnuof ruo fo trap era uoy
.og ot detnaw eh erehw saw
,reganam ruoy htiw seussi eht tuoba reilrae em dlot dah uoy dehsiw I“
.gnirob os s’taht dna yticirtcele tuoba gninrael er’eW
,OEC eht htiw enolA
egdelwonk siht ssap ot tog ev’uoy
”.ti otni krow tup ot deen uoy
?eb dluohs ti woh taht t’nsi tuB“
,triks a ni god wolley ,cihpromoporhtna ,llams a dna
tlef dah eh snoitome yawa deirub gnol denekawa eno gnidloH
.ereht erew uoy dna loohcs hguorht tnew I
.raw nonabeL eht tuoba eivom a was ecno I“
.reganam eht desserdda ehS
,mih detfig dah rehtaf sih agnam a ,10 remaT-
”.kcab teg uoy nehw em nioj emoC
.tneserp lla erew ynapmoc eht fo draob eht dna reganam sih
thgiew a ,rethgil eht lla tlef eh dna mlac ni mih depparw etelpmoc gnieb
.yaw doog a ni tub
.pu em kcab ot ydobemos evah I taht si
.niaga krow otni smrofsnart dne rehto eht ta dna
.dnah ni llits erutcip demarf eht
dna ni detropelet tsuj I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ynapmoc eht fo ecaf eht gnivas
,ecaf sih no kool duorp a htiw dna
,efil sih fo syad tseilenol eht fo eno sa dedne tI
.meht hguorht dellorcs eh dna
emas eht llits era erawdrah dna esac eht
kcab otohp eht tup eH .dias eH ”.emahS“
dezilaer eh taht neht saw tI
.daeherof nwo sih deppals eH ”…pukcaB“
ydegart ro ,egnahc fo ,diarfa regnol on ma I
.mih ot gnisserp erom lla tlef tsartnoc krats eht yadot
.tfel dah I emit eht fo tsom koot regnarts taht htiw retnuocne ruoy gnivresbo
loohcs fo edistuo seirrow yadyreve fo kcal eht
”.llew haey ,netsil ot syap tI“
yddub sknahT“ .dias natrapS
moc.yrrufos.ardik ta seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY .skrow sih ni
em ot eb dluoc siht tahw tuoba kniht I nehw dna tnerruc eht si elbairav si tahW
,gnilevart fo ruoh na revo retfA
.sevlow s’natrapS dna ratava xof ynootrac ,dlo sih saw
.skeew rof siht ot no dloh ot naht dnekeew a rof loof a retteB
”.negotorp a sa pu wohs ot uoy tcepxe t’ndid I“
:elpuoc ddo na doots hcaeb eht nO
tuoba ni uoy ot kcab teg I naC
.selpmaxe dlrow-laer erom dna snortcele ,srotcudnoc
”.ni knis siht tel dna skoob ym revo og ot tnaw I
?uoy tsol I taht deneppah tahW“
.detiaw tsuj noediG dna
,gnidaer ylno ton saw eh yadoT
.rednaw ezag sih tel dna
.ssalc scisyhP“ ”?cipot tluciffiD“
.flesym yaw taht eb ot dna ,tsixe ot
deticxe oot tlef noediG
”.ereh morf og uoy erehw ees ot deticxe ma I
.devil negotorp devoleb sih erehw
.nopu yler ,morf ecnadiug ward nac I taht
.emarf eno otni demmarc elpoep ynam htiw ylimaf yppah A
.ratava ruoy tuoba railimaf gnihtemos s’erehT
.won neppah dluow tahw derednow eh
rotavele eht otni demaerts elpoeP
.efil ni egats rehtona tsuj ;neppah ot dnuob
.ecalp ni llef eceip tsal ehT
.yltnereffid dediced emit siht tub
.epoh saw ereht nehT
rebmemer mih edam tI
daeha daor nwonknu eht nO
.noitaudarg retfa thgir ekorb stcatnoc emoS
,tcefrep saw thgin ehT
.noitceles ediw a
.tneilc eht ni gub fo dnik a ,thguoht eH
,taerg si siht ,noediG ,seY
ytilibissop fo dlrow a
.no gniog si taht lla tuoba erom uoy ot gniklat ot drawrof kool I tub ,won ffo daeh ot evah I taht yrros m’I .stnemom ym evah I sseug I“
,tuoba saw siht tahw fo hcnuh a dah noediG ”.ti teg
,selbats fo puorg a ot emac yeht nehW“
,oN‘ .flesmih detpurretni tub
.enola nials eb ton dluoc taht
ecnatsiser eht dna egarepma si
,etunim tsal devomer saw tinu gnilooc eht esuaceB
”.yppah em sekam ti sseug I tub
”.netfo oot thgil ruoy edih uoY
”?eb taht dluow tahW“
lennosrep ni segnahc yna rof
”.naem uoy tahw ees nac I .thgir er’uoy
emit revo yawa dedaf srehto
.gnineve lla uoy ot gninetsil neeb ev’I ,dog yM“
t’nsah ti ekil tsehc sih morf detaidar mlac dna htmraW
,rorrim eht ni elihw a rof flesmih ta dekool eh
.yadseuT txen no daeha pu gniteem lufdaerd a
.kciuq ylriaf revo saw gniteem ehT
.hguoht ,enola ton saw eh ,devirra eh nehW
”.em ot ffuts loohcs ym gninialpxe dna ecivda pihsnoitaler em gnivig emit siht lla tneps dna erehwon fo tuo emac uoY
gnihtemos dnuof neve eh won
.gnithgif erew uoy ekil dednuos tI“
.dehgis regnarts ehT
,yadot erahs ot gnihtemos dah I taht ykcul saw I sseug I
.yks eht ni snoom owt htiw hcaeb a delbmeser taht eno saw ereht
.demlehwrevo tlef I nehw dniwnu
mih dewollof ohw
.eb yam negotorp sih erehw dna og ot erehw aedi erom on dah eh sruoh retfA
neht pukcab nwo ym eb ot deen I
,deciton ylsuoicsnoc regnol on eh esion dnuorgkcab otni denrut evah seiromem demarf eseht sraey eht revO
.dnopser ot woh wonk ton did eh tub
.gnituohs god eht draeh eH
”?yhW .did ehs ,haey
,dehsinav eh erofeb tub
negotorp sih tuoba devol eh taht lla taht dezilaer eh dna
.ytilibisnopser ym si eh esuaceb ,ssenevigrof uoy ksa I dna ereh reenigne lacirtcele roines ruo ot snoitcurtsni evag I
,noitulos a gnidnif ni detseretni t’nsaw ehs ,melborp reh tuoba uoy dlot ehs nehw sseug I“
.tsap dellorcs sliat krahs htiw emos
.netsil reven I smialc ehS
.yllaitnatsbus ,evah I“
.dias yug gib ehT
,roolf eht no tlenk eh ,did eh nehw dna
.nihtiw morf emac
”.eerf rof sremotsuc ruo rof xif ew
.muminim a ot stsoc gnittuc
.gnidliub tnemtrapa sih fo rotavele dlo emas eht otni deppets eh niaga ecnO