sseltrihs doots eh sa kcab sih gnihcterts ,smra sih desiar eH
.ega htiw detalumucca dah taht taf fo reyal thgils a htiw
.eybdoog klofnogard eht devaw eh sa nirg
.seiretsam ruo dna seitiliba ruo no desab meht niatbo eW
,osrot sih fo sedis eht ot rednaw swap esned eht tlef hniroT
,noitanevujer fo syawhtap eht rof ydob a pu nesool ot elihw a sekat tI“
.renroc eht ni setarc wef a fo pot no dial gur derruf-etihw a dna
”.dnim t’now retniW erus m’I
.dehcuot tsomla stuons rieht sa gnimoclew dna mlac slipup sih
”!klofnogard ,yaw eht yb ,hO“
.edis eht ot revo detoocs eh sa derrup redniC ",neht lleW
.kcab sih no nwod eil ot pu flesmih depporp ylhsigguls eh sa derettum hniroT
.ti otni traeh ym ruop I ,laeh I nehw dna ,yoj em sgnirb srehto laeh oT“
.nibac sih ot rood eht denepo eh sa
.emosrebmuc ylralucitrap saw tnemlia thgils sih yadot tub
,kcab etihw ,daorb eht demaor tac gib eht sa erusserp deilppa swap mraw ,tfos ehT
,klofnogard eht ffo swap ytsaot sih gnikaT
,noitisop siht nI
.erofeb stnemom tsuj ti no gniyal neeb dah tac gib eht fi sa mraw gur eht
,erom ecno osrot sih dehcaer yeht sA
”.ilteuH rof si taht ,seY !hA“
.dedulcnoc klofnogard ehT ”.eurt sleef tI
,wolg mid eht detcelfer yeht sa sloop dicalp ekil dewolg slipup esohw
.kcab ediw sih derevoc taht sepirts nedlog eht yb detautnecca
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”,emit siht erom tib a flesym trexe ot detnaw I“
.sdrow deggaj eht revo swap sih decart eh sa mih fo retteb eht gnitteg ytisoiruc sih
”.noitavresbo etutsa nA“
.htaeneb htgnerts eht gnileef dna selacs tfos eht no sbmuht sih gnicart
.meht fo htob eht morf hgual llams a gnitteg
,larutannu meht gnillac
,sdohtem gnilaeh larutan no deiler yllausu ew dnalemoh ym ni kcaB“ .deriuqni hniroT
.sdnal eci nrehtron eht ni nwot eht ni kcab
.mrof suoreneg sih htaenrednu gnitfihs yllanoisacco elcsum fo selppir htiw
seye enilef sih ni deraeppa tnilg yls dna
.ekawa yats ot noitasrevnoc edam eh dna
,mra dna dnah sih no tser ylleb tfos s’regit nedlog eht tlef hniroT
.tser s’thgin doog a gnitteg yllanif retfa leef dluow eh woh derednow eH
,emit emos rof feileb siht dleh I“
.regit ,em tpmet t’noD“
.deruc gnieb ssenlli na ro dednem gnieb dnuow a tuoba ylno ton si tI
t’nod klofnogard taht wonk I ecnis s’ti esoppus I !rehtie hcum dog nogard elbon eht gnimialcorp uoy ees t’nod I“
.ruf tfos eht tsniaga gnibbur selacs kcab sih
”.eveileb dnalemoh ym fo klofnogard eht fo emos tahw si taht tsael tA
.pihs eht fo yawllah ytekcir ,dloc eht nwod deklaw klofnogard eht
.enalP dehcrocS-nuS dlo eht fo snogard eht ot dengila eb ot si liat a evah ot yas yehT“
.degnahc tahwemos evah cigam gnilaeh no sweiv ym
”?skram eseht evah klofnogard elacsthgirB eht fo lla oD“
.swap latrom ruo otni secrof eht psarg ot seutriv evah ew tuB
”.nosaer doog a rof dna ,tra ruoy ni edirp ekat uoY“
dlohwollaH fo ytic dellaw ,yci eht ni gniteem ymoolg ,detcepxenu rieht fo seiromem feirb sa flesmih ot thguoht hniroT
.delkcuhc tsuj klofnogard eht hcihw ot ,dezigolopa redniC
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,esuap a retfa deksa redniC
.kcab ralucsum s’klofnogard etihw eht no swap sih decalp eH
.swalc sih fo spit eht ta deraeppa thgil nedlog fo sehsalf llams dna
.elpoep tnereffid ot sgniht tnereffid snaem tpecnoc eht taht tsuj s’ti ,em evigroF
.rewolf gniremmihs ,erutainim a gnitaerc
.ygrene htiw elppir selacs sih gnileef ,tsehc sih dexelf eH .deilper hniroT
”.hcuot detcerid erom a deen uoy ,stnemlia suoivbo ssel ,repeed rof tub ,sdnuow lareneg gnidnem rof doog si cigam gnilaeh fo egrus lufrewop A“ ”.yzzuf leef I“
”.raef ot gnihton evah uoy neht
.evol fo sseddog a depihsrow uoy taht kniht t’ndid I ,hguoht yas tsum I“
”.hniroT ,htraeh ym ta emoclew syawla er’uoY“ ”.ylurT
.evael ot denrut klofnogard eht sa ylmraw kcab dellac redniC
.cigam htiw gnippird llits erew hcihw swap sih gnibbur ,deksa redniC
”.htmraw rednet s’remmus a fo murcalumis dloc A
,semit erom wef a selcsum s’hniroT dedaenk regit ehT
.revo mih dekrow regit yrrebwarts ytfeh eht sa seye sih desolc hniroT
,mlap sih morf demossolb emalf nedlog fo sdnarts eniF
.emahs ot em stup sgniddeb fo eciohc ruoY“ .detnurg hniroT
.sbir ruoy neewteb elcsum nrot a evah uoy eveileb I“
ta lla erew srentrap ym eveileb I hguohT
.redniC ,uoy knahT“ .dekrims hniroT
.ruf mraw ,yvaeh htiw mlap sih gnirevoc
.snoitrexe tneserp sih morf taews fo neehs thgil a dna
.ruf nedlog s’enilef eht hguorht detcelfer noitanimulli fo srevils htiw
.mih htaeneb rits efil eht gnileef
.wef a evah ot etanutrof erew erdaC elacsthgirB ew hguoht
.elims yldneirf a htiw nwod dekool regit ytfeh eht ,mih evobA
.klofnogard eht bur yltneg ot deunitnoc eh sa deilper redniC
”?saw eman reh eveileb I ,allibyS
…flesym taht od nac I
”.uoy htiw thgirla s’taht fi ,thginot enod er’ew nehw ykcits dna mraw tib a leef lliw selacs ruoY
.tabmoc htiw ngila taht srewop yllaicepse
,.drow tsal eht derettum eh sa teiuq gniworg eciov sih
.noihsuc elpma edivorp ot hguone esned tub
.seye sih desolc dna delbmur nogard ehT
.erom ecno ydob sih no swap sih ecalp ot nwod tneb kloftac eht dna ,deddon hniroT
.deb eht ffo debmilc dna klofnogard dezad eht morf pu tog regit yrrebwarts eht
”.sdog dlo eht ot ytiniffa regnorts a leef llits I
”.wohs ton seod ti hguoht neve ,nogard elbon eht reppihsrow a llits ma I dnA
,wap egral eht fo spit walc dehtaehs eht morf deppird cigaM
erihsehc ,yffulf a mih evag tsuj kloftac eht tub ,detrats hniroT “-I“ ”.ehriv sydguhr rtyh rudatsi korhE ,rtiamrof osihe rtyh raborkas korhE
,liat ym tsol I fI“
tsehc sih eveiler swap yvaeh esoht tlef eh sa flesmih gnirrup tsomla ,deilper hniroT ”,hA“
.yad remmus mraw a no ssarg gnuoy ,etaciled gnihsurb ekilnu ton
.flesti noitarotser fo ssecorp eht tuoba si tI
,ti fo erac ekat dluow tser fo keew a taht thguoht eH
.noitcaretni etamitni erom eht yojne yllaer od I tuB
,flesti gnilaeh fo tca eht no sucof ot tnatropmi si ti tuB
”.sfeileb rieht erahs ot ytinutroppo eht ta depmuj scirelc tsom thguoht I ?yawyna ,uoy t’nevah yhW“ .derednop hniroT ”.evah uoy eveileb t’nod I ?sey ,dog ruoy si ilteuH“ ”?I evah ,reh tuoba uoy dlot reven ev’I
,tsaoc nretsew eht ot gnilevart dna erdaC elacsthgirB eht gninioj retfa hguoht
,tser ot edis s’hniroT yb nwod tas eh sa deilper redniC
.dnem uoy elpoep eht tuoba tol a nrael uoY“
stipmra s’klofnogard eht woleb dehcnelc redniC
,sdrawpu dils yeht sa ylthgil dezeeuqs swap eht
.selacs dna selcsum thgit sih xaler ot secalp thgir eht lla ni cigam gnihtoos fo spsiw gnidnes
”.regit ,suoivbo oot
.seye sih denepo eh sa deilper redniC ”,sseddog eht ot gnireffo ronim a ylno s’tahT“
”.tfos siht erew swap regit wonk t’ndid I“
.shtnom wef tsap eht rof emoh dellac eh taht pihsria dlo eht fo kced rewol eht ot sriats eht nwod debmilc eh sa hguoc a delfits klofnogard etihw ehT
htaerb hcae htiw llef dna esor ylleb dna tsehc elpma s’tac gib eht sa dehctaw hniroT
.gnikniht ,swap nwo sih ta derats eh sa yltfos deilper redniC
,hcamots sih fo sedis eht gnippirG
.denialpxe rehtruf redniC
”.ereh gnihtemos eb dluow ereht taht larutan smees tI“
tem tsrif yeht nehw ereht ton saw taht erus ytterp saw eH
.edaf ot detrats snoitacove eht sa ,detnap hniroT
”,flesym ti od nac I“ .deksa redniC
.sresuort pmeh ,desu-llew fo tes a gniraew
.su fo htob rof deb eht no ecaps hguone s’ereht kniht I“
.luos ni gnikcal si ti taht yas lliw I tuB
,sseworp laitram sih deyalpsid eroc dna tsehc sih fo selcsum yklub ehT
.ytuaeb no yliramirp sesucof ehs ,wonk I tahw morf
!uoy rof elbatius s’ti dalg m’I“ ”.emahs
.flesmih ot thguoht hniroT ,redniC ekil tac a rof gnittif yreV
.eniw nevle enif fo elttob a barg ot moor egarots eht yb deppots ylfeirb eh ,dnuora gninruT
.flesti evol ton si ti tub
,gnignahc era semiT .suoiruc llits ma I“
s’tahT“ ”.traeh yvaeh a evah uoY“ .dennirg hniroT
,swap sih ni ecnuob tsehc s’klofnogard eht dehctaw eh sa elzzum s’enilef eht no degreme elims eltbus A
”?stneitap rieht htiw lacisyhp siht yllausu stseirp dna scirelc erA“
”.seidob ruo snetfos ti taht dna
”?reffo na taht sI“
.ruf s’regit eht no decnuob dna meht dnuora swodahs tsac thgil egnaro mraw ehT
,sredluohs s’hniroT no yvaeh yal swap s’redniC
tsol owT .ecnaegneV dna emiT .ehriV vuh rtiamroF“.skram sih no swap eht fo hcuot eht no gnisucof dna moor eht fo ecnelis eht ni gnikat
,klofnogard eht fo selcsum dna selacs eht otni pees cigam sih tlef eh sa derrup dna seye sih desolc redniC
.osrot derujni s’klofnogard eht no yal hcihw
”.dnalemoh ruoy fo gnilaeh lacigam fo amgits eht tuoba em dlot uoy ecniS“
"?tsehc ruoy slia gnihtemos denoitnem uoY"
.taefed dna ,yrotciv ,elttab ecneirepxe oT
.won rof ,ecneserp s’klofnogard yranecrem eht esoppo yltcerid ton od I yhw si tI
.emas eht era skram ruo lla ton dnA
,sdiurd dna scirelc eht fo scigam gnilaeh eht tsurt ton od llits sredle ynaM
”.drow a fo erusare eht naem dluoc rebmem erdaC elacsthgirB a fo htaed ehT
selacs hguor s’klofnogard eht no elbaeciton ylerab eb ot hguone thgil ruf eht
"!ni emoc ,ereh eno ylno eht m'I
”?em tuoba kniht uoy od tahw ,won
.elcsum fo bals kciht eht otni ylpeed sbmuht sih desserp dna
,kcab eht morf dluoc I sa gnilaeh hcum sa deilppa I“
',thguoht I naht redrah em kcurts yllautca tnaig taht
”?cinocard sehcton eseht erA
rednet dna dnik seye dicalp ,revlis s’redniC
”.tceridni erom hcum eb nac sdohtem gnilaeh rieht decneirepxe I tahw morf tuB“
,hA“ ”.srehto wef a dna uoy rof tpecxe srelaeh citsym htiw ecneirepxe elttil evah I os
.slarotcep sih fo edisrednu eht ecart swap s’redniC gnileef ,deilper hniroT
.dneirf ,sdrow dnik eht rof uoy knahT“
.gnimrasid oot si ronaemed siH“
.dedda redniC ”.em llet uoy erus ekam ,snruter niap eht fI“
.stnaig htiw tnemegagne suoiverp rieht morf tnorf ralucsum sih no deniamer sesiurb dna sracs wef A
.deffuhc relaeh kloftac eht ".gnihton
,ruf dna ydob tfos s'regit eht no decnad swodahs dna thgil eht ,slwob eht fo emos evom ot gnitfihS
.dnim d'uoy kniht t'ndid I .etal etiuq si tI"
.tsehc s’hniroT no slobmys ecart ot nageb enilef eht
.rennam siht ni euqisyhp sih enimaxe ot enoemos wolla ot epyt eht eb dluow klofnogard taht kniht t’ndid I“
.hguorht og ylsseltroffe dluow ti dna
.delaeh eb ot ton era yehT“
.sregnil llits gnilaeh edistuo ot roirepus gnieb htgnerts nwo ym yb gnirevocer fo thguoht eht tuB
.ecneirepxe gnitarogivni dna lanosrep erom hcum a pu snepo ti tub
.degnahc evah sgniht ynaM“
".gnol oot rof ruf ym tsniaga bur yeht nehw elbatrofmocnu teg sebor yM"
,enobliat s’klofnogard eht ot nwod selacs eht decart yeht
,hA“  ”.eno delacs taerg eht yb em ot dewotseb rewop fo sdrow eht era esohT
.gnireffo elpmis A“
.dewaffug klofnogard ehT
.eciov sih desiar eh sa niap fo gnap thgils eht ta gnicniw ,ylffurg dias eH ".hniroT
.elims tfos a evag tsuj redniC hcihw ot ,delkcuhc hniroT
ylleb rewol s’tac gib eht fo hsulp tfos eht tlef eh sa tnemom a rof denepo seye s’hniroT
.gninaem niatbo yeht od neht ylno rof
oggodneP yb ”sretrauQ s’relaeH ehT“   yojne esaelP
”.taht ta eno etabilec a yllaicepsE“ .derrup redniC
.ylteiuq derettum redniC ”,siht em dlot ohw klofnogard tsrif eht ton er’uoY“
.meht neewteb tcatnoc eht fo erawa erom neve tlef hniroT
.erus ton m’I…“ .deksa hniroT
.gur eht no tas eh sa edis sih yb yal stnenopmoc dna ,seirreb ,sbreh htiw dellif slwob wef A
.mryw eulb a rof tneloveneb rehtar neeb sah elur sih ,eurt si tahT“
,aera eht egassam ot deunitnoc regit eht
,seye tfos htiw hniroT ta nwod dekool redniC
”,tnorf ni selacs renif dna rehtooms evah od yllaer klofnogard uoY“
,deveiler saw kcab sih no erusserp eht sa ssenitpme fo esnes ddo na saw erehT
,derumrum hniroT
ydob a otno decrof eb ot ton si gnilaeH .hself eht no lufsserts eb nac gnilaeh yvaeh htiw gnieb a gnikcohs taht no ylrae denrael evah ,ygrene gnilaeh fo ecnadnuba ym ot eud ,yllaicepse ,I“ .tsehc mraw s’klofnogard eht no yltfos nwod desserp eh sa ,deffuhc redniC
.rewop fo sdrow eht fo tsal eht gnicart dehsinif eh sa deilper redniC
.tneitap sih otni thgiew sih denael eh sa sedalb redluohs s’klofnogard eht otni swap sih dehsup enilef ehT
”.eno sa seidob owt fo noinu ehT
.evoba seye enilef eht yb decitonnu t’nsaw ecnalg gnitfihs ehT
,pirg mrif a htiw tub ,tfoS
”,gnihtyna gnitruh fo elbapac era sruoy fo swap esoht erus ton m’I“
.denialpxe kloftac ehT
,ygrene dna noisicerp detcepxenu deniatnoc tey
.tsehc s’klofnogard eht no kcab swap sih gnicalp
.melborp a saw ereht fi dnaherofeb uoy denraw evah dluow I“
.retnab emos detrats eh sa delbmur hniroT
.tegrof reven llahs traeh ym sdrow
.tnemtnio tnargarf fo lwob llams a koot eh
,deksa redniC ”?snogard fo srewop eht gnissenrah fo deracs teg reve uoy oD“
hgis tfos a ehtaerb tub pleh t’ndluoc klofnogard ehT
.moor eht otni deklaw dna gnipacse morf ria mraw eht tneverp ot ylteiuq rood eht desolc hniroT
ecaf sih no gniregnil elims llams a
”.stipmra ruoy sdrawot gniliart
.elbamatnu dna ylurnu era eroc rieht ta taht
.nosrep rehto eht htiw tcennoc ot deen uoY
,spih s'hniroT no ylthgil detser eH
.tloj neddus a htiw
.dekrims hniroT ”,pu delir siht uoy nees ev’I emit tsrif eht s’tI“
”.eraps ot cigam emos evah I dedivorp
.hcuot sih ot yltneg dewolg slobmys enacra tniaf sa dnah sih werdhtiw eH
.laeh ot sdnuow ronim erom rof gnihcraes
.kcab s’hniroT revo cigam elkcirt ot nwod dehcterts redniC sa mih revo dessap wodahs A
”.tsael yrev eht ta ,sregnif fo elpuoc a gnisol ekil eb dluow ti
.gnilaeh fo sseddog s’dnalemoh ym si ilteuH
.krow rieht deunitnoc swap egral sih sa dias redniC
.ydob a dnem ot yaw doog a ton si hself otni cigam gnilennahc ylpmis taht eveileb od I
.kcab deppans dnim sih sa ezad thgils a ni mih tpek hcihw
.ecnaegnev lortnoc ew lliw fo htgnerts hguorhT
.seitiroirp tnereffid ylediw evah nac niamod emas eht rednu scirelc woh gnitanicsaf s’tI“
.gnihton si siht ,hsuh hO"
.mlab gniregnil a evaew ot tnemtnio desufni emos ylppa ll’I os ,peed etiuq s’tI
,delims tac egral ehT
.erom ecno hgual ot owt eht gnitteg ,slarotcep ylrub s’klofnogard eht gnitfeh ,derednop redniC
,dehcterts dna esor redniC sa devom ria ehT
”.tser ot ekil klofnogard woh erus yllaer ton m’I
,oggodneP yb ”sretrauQ s’relaeH ehT“ saw sihT
.dnem ot sdnuow rof dehcraes yeht sa selacs fo niatnuom eht gnimaor
”.taht uoy evig ll’I ,nuf yrev era sliat kloftaC“
,deunitnoc eh sa tnemeerga ni derumrum tsuj redniC
.spitregnif sih morf egreme ecno ton did yeht sa lortnoc luflliks ni swalc sih
.nirg yffulf ,gums s’redniC ees ot seye sih gnisucofer
,sredluohs s’hniroT krow ot cigam tnetop sih gnivaeL
,ecaf sih morf yawa sehcni wef a htolcniol niht eht ta gnicnalg
”.edivorp tonnac cirelc elpmis a gnihtemoS
,spih s’klofnogard eht fo edis hcae no erew shgiht yfeeb siH
.nemodba sih fo selacs elap eht ssorca depard htolcniol klis ,ydnugrub eht dna
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
”.yademos ti ta retteb teg ot epoh I tub ,rettal eht ni elbapac yrev eb tey ton thgim I“
”,ti t’nsah ,elihw a etiuq neeb s’tI“
.yerp sti gniklats retnuh a ekilnu ton
.melborp a etiuq llits s’tahT"
”.llew stnehZ esoht wonk od yllaer uoY“
,sserp yvaeh yreve htiw eglub slarotcep dna smra s’regit nedlog eht ni selcsum eht dehctaw hniroT
.krow redniC dehctaw eh sa sdrow sih fo tuo gnippils eugnothcard ,deilper hniroT
.liat sselerac s’redniC yawa hsurb dna mra sih tfil ot delggurts eh sa deilper
,tem seye rieht staeb traeh wef a roF
.klofnogard eht fo eroc ydruts eht gnigassam
ot elba neeb t’nevah uoy taht emahs a s’tI“
.smlap rieht hguorht cigam gnitaidar yb ro
tahT“ .derussaer hniroT ”.kloftac ,ereht tuoba yrrow ot gnihton evah uoY“
ydob sih deretne dna selacs sih revo decart taht cigam fo sliart ehT
…sseddoG deriah-riaF ehT“
.yas ot tahw fo thguoht eh sa sredluohs yklub eht otni swap sih gnidaenk
.tnorf eht morf gnimoc si tsehc ruoy ni niap eht fo hcum tub
.cinut sih rednu tsehc sih gnileef
”?emuser ew llahS .og ew erehT“
,flesmih ot derettum eH
.pu tog eh sa detnurg hniroT ”.moor
,denaorg hniroT ”!kloftac ,sdog eht yB !kcuF“
.gnorts eb yllaer
”.ytsat yrev era erujnoc uoy seirreb esohT“
.eciton t’ndid klofnogard eht neve taht sracs ronim gnilaeh
,gur eht no nwod kcab llef eh sa dedaf ylwols kcab sih no ssenizzuf ehT
,knurt s’klofnogard eht ot nwod kcab derednaw swap s’redniC
.emac gnihton tub ,tsehc sih ni egniwt a gnitcepxe ,flesmih decarb eH
.ylleb sih no yal dna
.thgin ruoy no gnisopmi eno eht m'I ,sediseB .dnim t'nod I"
.ria looc eht ot desopxe saw tnorf sih sa revihs thgils a evag eH
.rood nibac eht denepo eh sa klofnogard eht deteerg ria mraW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.htiw elbatrofmoc si tnehZ taht tahw htiw desirprus eb d’uoY“ ”.rennam
,lio htiw sregnif sih fo ruf eht gnikaoS
”,dneirf ,yrrow t’noD“
.mih dnuorrus kloftac tfos eht fo htmraw eht tlef nhiroT
”.sliat on evah klofnogard yhw derednow syawla ev’I“
.dennirg hniroT
taht yas ot sa raf sa og ton lliw I“
”.elpmaxe hcus eno si reahtravlakS
.moor eht dnuora denaelg dna ni deklaw eh
,selacs s’klofnogard eht hguorht nar regnif sih sA
.meht tsurt ot tluciffid yllaicepse s’ti dna
.rof nraey dluow eh enigami ton did eh trofmoc a saw cigam gniwolf eht htiw denibmoc s’enilef depirts eht fo erusserp etarebiled tey ,eltneg ehT
.pihsnoinapmoc fo esnes peed a gnivig
,rehto eht no regit eht dna edis eno no pihs eht fo llaw nedoow eht htiW
.elihw a ni ecno gnireffo fo dnof m’I taht noitoved fo mrof llams a s’tI“
.yllausac dias redniC
.slevart rieht gnirud gur eht deriuqca evah thgim redniC erehw dna
,dekrow eh sa ruf s’enilef eht no gnimrof saw taews fo neehs thgil A
,eye ot eye teem syawla ton yam eW“ .derussaer hniroT
,swap sih morf detpure cigam gnilaeh fo tsrub yvaeh A
”?elbatrofmoc uoy erA“
.cigam lufrewop htiw gnimmirb tey
.sllaw nibac eht fo eno tsniaga gninael
tnelis dna htooms erew stnemevom siH
”.ti referp t’nod I tuB
.yldehsaba ,dennirg redniC ”,taht etaicerppa I hcum woh wonk t’nod uoY“
.nirg dessarrabme ylthgils a htiw gnihctiwt rae
”.yllamron ehtaerb dna xaler esaelp oS
.moor ym ot kcab teef wef a klaw t’ndluoc I fi reidlos a eb t’ndluow I ,sediseB ?sih si gur tahT“
”.esnes luftsul dna citnamor eht htob ni ,evoL“ ”.snoitan
.htmraw rieht htiw meht gninetfos ,selcsum yraew sih hguorht tlef yltrepxe swap egral esohT
,rtiamrof osihe rtyh raborkas korhE“
”.doog rof dnem ot ysae eb dluohs ti ,morf gnimoc si ehca eht erehw wonk I taht woN“
”.gnildnik enif ni rebme etaciled a gniltsen ekiL“
.dnim sih hguorht dehsalf oga snoom xis
”.ni trap ekat ot tnaw ton od I taht eno dna ,ytilaivirt ni esicrexe na si
.thgil eht ni dlog gniremmilg seye revlis sih
.trofmocsid esuac ton ot luferac tub klofnogard eht no thgiew gniylppa dniheb tfos sih
,seye sih desolc klofnogard ehT
,deksa regit gib eht ”?sgnisselb rehtO“
.taht rebmemer ll’I“
.thginot ereh eil nac uoy ,derit oot leef uoy fI
rettiwt no tra sih dna
ydob s’nrobnogard eht nwod dna pu demaor swap s’redniC
.swap detnelat s’regit eht yb tuo dehsup ylwols saw tsehc sih ni ria eht dna
.liat elbixelf nwo sih htiw daeh eht no yllufyalp klofnogard eht deppob eh sa deffuhc redniC ”!sselesu t’nera yehT“
.yrujni eht otni demoolb cigam gnilaeh fo skraps sa dehsinav ylkciuq ti tub ,mossolb niap fo tnih thgils a tlef hniroT
”.tegrof
.tabmoc ni ytilibail dna ytimertxe esool rehtona naem ylno dluow liat a gnivah ,ytilacitcarp nI“ .detnurg hniroT
.ecneitaP dna htgnertS .raborkaS vuh
.secruos ynam morf emoc nac htgnerts taht wonk ot hguone gnol delevart evah I
,ecneirepxe eht ot hcuot yzzuf a dedda
.yltniaf gniwolg selacs sih no sdrow eht
.thgil eht ni yltfos maelg selacs sih gnikam cigam dna tnemtnio fo dnelb eht
,drow elgnis a htiw laeh nac scirelc ynaM“
.klis ydnugrub eht no eniltuo tniaf eht ta gnitrad
.rae gnihsulb ,gnihctiwt sih ta tab ot wap a detfil regit ehT
.tser s’thgin a retfa retteb hcum leef dluohs uoY“
”.enoemos dneffo ylirassecennu ot hsiw ton od I
rehtona gnilaeh fo secnaun repeed eht dnatsrednu yeht nac woH“
,llew sa noehtnap nahsiM eht ni koot yllautneve ew hguohT
.…sseddog rehto eht ekil eb thgim ti gnikniht saw I
.yademos redro ni eb ot deen dluow noisses gnilaeh rehtona
.elcsum dna elacs yreve tuo deppam eh sa
,yzzuf dna tfos saw gur etihw ehT
,live era snogard citamorhc lla ton ,sediseB“
…nemodba ruoy steem tsehc ruoy erehw yllaicepsE“ .deton redniC
,stnemlia ronim rehto yna rof nruter ot emoclew er’uoY“
.mih demlehwrevo snoitasnes eht sa regit eht fo pirg mrif eht ni naorg a rettu tub pleh t’ndluoc hniroT .sserac yrehtaef a htiw hself s’klofnogard eht gnimaor ygrene fo slirdnet mraw
,redniC ta pu dekool hniroT
.yb pord d'uoy dias uoy rebmemer I"
”.eugnothcarD fo tcelaid dlo eht ni nettirw si ti hguoht ,cinocard era yeht ,deednI
”.nogard etihw a fo ecneiliser eht ,rudatsI“
”.erofeb tnega miratnehZ eht delaeh ev’I“
.efil fo sklaw tnereffid ynam morf semoc ytrap ruo dnA“
”.ytilatipsoh eht esuba thgim tsuj I
,seutriv eht tuo kees stcepsa eseht spahreP
.selacs denedrah sih ni sehctarcs peed eht ta ecart ylthgil swap eht deciton hniroT
,owt esoht htiw eci eht kaerb ot drah s’tI“ .dias hniroT
,tsehc ralucsum sih ssorca dedilg wap s’redniC
,spih sih hguorht dewolf slirdnet tnetop eht fo tsal eht sA
.hctaw ot gniziremsem saw esitrepxe htiw ssenlufyalp dexim regit ytfeh eht hcihw htiw esae ehT
.deifiralc hniroT
,rewop htiw semoc taht noitpurroc fo ksir a syawla si erehT“
.relaeh eht sdrawot delbma eh sa devresbo klofnogard ehT ".redniC
.der srae sih ,dias redniC
.ylleb sih dehctarcs yldednimtnesba eh sa ylyhs detfihs eH
,detatiseh hniroT ”…ytiliriv .…animats …wonk uoY“ .gnihctiwt rae
…llits si gnireffo derovaf tsom ehT“
.gur eht otni yltfos derettum hniroT
…ecnaegnev dna emiT“
.nohgroM ni delttes ew erofeb neve
.yartsa del eb ton lliw I ,thgil s’nogarD ehT yb tuB
stcepsa gnisoppo dna lufrewop owt
.ylpeed derrup redniC
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR  .ykseulb ro
,yletelpmoc dehsinav dah moor eht fo ecnaibma mraw ehT
.redleiw eht ot euqinu era emoS
,morf emac gur eht lamina tahw derednop ylfeirb eH
,ylpeed oot ni dehtaerb ro dehguoc eh revenehw demoolb tsehc sih ni niap gniregnil llams A
”.peels ot em llul ot gninetaerht si ereh erehpsomta eht
”.yltfos dna yltneg ,ni dexaoc eb dluohs ti ,ydob a dnem oT
.ylleb s’redniC htaeneb dennirg hniroT ”.scirelc
,nwod dewob tac gib ehT
.ylleb deroloc-maerc sih revo dils yldednimtnesba liat etihw-nedlog sih dna
.dehgis redniC ”.feiler a s’tahT“
.dekcolnu saw tlob a sa edis rehto eht morf tuo dellac eciov tfos A "!hniroT"
retirw lausac dna tsitra yrruf a si ohw
.sedis sih maor neht ot
”.evah t’ndluohs I gnihtemos deldnah yllatnedicca I fi em evigrof
”…ehriv sydguhr rtyh rudatsi korhE
;hguoht ,wenk klofnogard eht gniht eno saw erehT
”.erif fo dog a ebyam ro …sporc fo dog a spahrep saw ti thguoht fo dnik I
.ruf tfos eht hguorht wolg tniaf a gniduxe llits
”.ydob eht fo snoitom dna swolf eht dna
.htmraw dna erutsiom erom part ot elba gnieb ruf tfos eht
”.tac taht dnatsrednu t’nod llits I“
.selacs hguor eht hguorht gnicart
”?sporc fo dog a hguohT
.hsarobrihT sa tsilatnemadnuf sa ecalp a ni neve
.htob tsniaga elggurts eht ni tsol teg ot ysae si tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,tfos tey yvaeh dna gnorts erew swap siH
.yawllah s’pihs eht denil taht semalf lacigam fo yarra eht yb yawa dehsup thgin eht fo ssenkrad eht
,tnemom a rof llits doots yehT
.drager hgih ni taht dloh t’nod I
.tnatsni na ni sdnuow slaeh yllufecrof taht cigam gnilaeh fo kcohs detartnecnoc a yolpme yehT
.yllufreehc detseggus redniC
.sdlrow ysatnaf dna syug gib sevol ohw
.mih no nwod gnihsaw tnecs dna htaerb mraw sih
.hsarobrihT ,dnalemoh sih fo skcarrab eht ni srodo regnorts raf decneirepxe dah klofnogard ehT
hniroT ”,taht uoy evig ll’I ,gnihtemos yletinifed si gnilaeh ruoY“
,erar erew scirelC
,evol rof tnatropmi era noitcartta lacisyhp dna ytuaeB
,osrot s’klofnogard eht ta nwod kcab dezag eH
.modeerf ruo kcab dloh lliw egadneppa sselesu eht taht wohs ot
ksum elam larutan s’regit eht htiw dexim htrae dna sbreh tniaf fo tnecs ehT
,mih tfel htgnerts s’hniroT ,gnilaeh fo seniv suocsiv eht ni depparW
.no yal eh gur eht fo ruf tfos eht otni tlem dluoc eh fi sa gnileef
,ylleb dna tsehc sih fo selacs eht otni depees htmraW
,srettam laivirt rof enoyna rehtob ot tnaw t'ndid yllamron eH
”.secaps thgit ytterp emos ni tif nac I tub ,ti ekil kool t’nseod tI
.htaenrednu demoolb thgil tfos dna tsehc sih fo elcsum dekcap eht no nwod desserp sdap wap tevlev ehT
,kram sih gnidniF
”.llew sa mih tcepser
,gur eht no tnecs eht dezingocer noos eh ,htaerb a gnikaT
”.taht detcepxe evah dluohs I“
”,ton ro elbmuh gnieb tsuj er’uoy fi llet t’nac I“ ”.desaelp tsael
.meht yb derreted gnitteg si cigam ym …skram esehT“
.sedalb redluohs sih tsniaga swap s’redniC fo thgiew eht tlef hniroT
,dedired redniC ”!?hself eht fo noitaicerppa na tuohtiw
”.gnitseretni erom gnihtemos em lleT“
,stnenopmoc ym ni seidemer labreh gnisu yB
,yrd dna mraw saw moor tcapmoc eht ni ria ehT
.meht ot dnuob era ew taht kram A
.hself sih dehcuot tnemtnio desufni-cigam ,gniremmihs ylthgils eht sa taeh elbatrofmocnu tsomla na tlef hniroT
…htiw setyloca reh wotseb ,re ehs seod ,evol fo sseddog a si ilteuH ecniS“
ymotana s’hniroT fo sevruc eht gnitagivan yltrepxe
,deilper redniC ”!hO“ ”?tnemwodne…“
,redniC tsap gnizeeuqs ,elbatrofmoc tog eH
,elihw a rof tnelis deniamer owt ehT
.klofnogard eht fo pot no gnittauqs flesmih gninoitisop ,deb eht no debmilc dna pu tog yltfed regit ehT
,spit wap s’redniC morf llef cigam fo stelpord thgiL
,maerd a erew ti fi sa tsomla
”.pihs depmarc siht ni noitoved ruoy ecitcarp
tsum redluohs hcae no sdrow eseht fo thgiew eht sdloh taht enO
.evitceffeni si gnilaeh rieht
.edis s’redniC ta htmraw fo ebuc lacigam a morf detaname thgil wolley ,mid A
,ylippah devaw htiw deitrap dah eh kloftac depirts ,ybbuhc ,suoiretsym ylthgils ehT
.dne eht ta ylthgils ecniw diurd regit eht gniciton ,dias hniroT
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
,scirelc rehto htiw tcaretni yllausu t’nod I
.tnemom elgnis a ni elbissop sa hcum sa dnem ot elba gnieb si yretsaM
.daeh sih gnikahs
.live lla ton era nohgroM fo secnirp eht taht flesruoy llew wonk uoY“ .dedda hniroT ”,eveileb uoy evah dluow elpoep dna klofnogard emos sa
.denialpxe redniC
,oga elihw a tuoba gniklat erew ew tahw ot kcab gnioG“
,tnemom a rof gnitatiseH
”.I sa hcus klofnogard derit a rof nevE
”.rehtona ot efil eno ,tuo gnihcaeR
.selacs s’hniroT otni devlossid ylwols slatep eht fo tsal eht sa ,dias redniC
.deb eht no yltneg gnittis regit nedlog ,yknuhc eht ta eye ot eye gnikool ,edistuo morf kcab decnalg hniroT
”.dneirf ,elbatrofmoc naht eroM“ .hniroT deksa redniC
.cigam gnilaeh yvaeh eht ni gniksab
,sregnif sih otni kcab dehtaehs ylluferac erew slian detniop ehT
,ylper ni edarmoc sih ot nirg a htiW
.hcuot sih ot mraw ylwols kcab s’hniroT no selacs eht tlef eH
,dneirf sih ta ylmraw delims eh ,deb eht gnittaP
,selacs dna tlep ni ecnereffid eht ot eud
,cinut sih ffo koot eh sa deilper hniroT
”.hsarobrihT ni tsae kcab yllaicepse ,sdog pihsrow yllaer
.stnemtnahcne erom wef a deraperp eh sa klofnogard eht revo gninael ,esor eH .deffuhc redniC
thgir em gnilaeh ysub er’uoy ecnis ,lleW“
,redniC ,yrruh retteB“
.sgnul sih deretne ssenelam fo tnecs tniaf eht
”?yaw siht delaeh ev’uoy klofnogard tsrif eht ton m’I“ .deksa hniroT
.deilper regit nedlog eht ”,sediseb dnA .tser doog a teg uoy taht tseb s’ti
.tsehc sih revo hsaw regit eht fo gnitnap mraw eht tlef hniroT
.redniC ,ereht elbatrofmoc etiuq kool uoY"
.slaog ym fo eno osla s’taht dnA
.edis hcae ta deppots yeht litnu sredluohs daorb s’klofnogard eht derednaw swap s’redniC
.rae sih otni gnirepsihw
”?uoy tpurroc dluoc nogard citamorhc a fo ecneulfni eht tahT“
.hguoht tnereffid si gnilaeh ruoY
flesti evol fo noissap eht fo daetsni ssenevitcartta fo eulav eht ezisahpme oT
.tabmoc sa hcus ,sesac ynam ni gnilaeh ni ycneidepxe fo ecnatropmi eht ezingocer I
.thginot od nac ew tahw ees s'tel dna nwod eiL"
”.dneirf ,llew taht rebmemer dluohs I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.noitacove tnetop htiw tnemtnio eht gnitarutas
,yrujni fo tniop cificeps eht rof gnihcraes tsuj m’I .gnihtoN“ ”?tahW“
.deunitnoc regit nedlog ehT
ytiniffaruf no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.thgil eht ot ylleb dna tsehc sih fo selacs etihw-enob ,renif eht gnisopxe
,detfil cigam fo ezah yzzuf eht sA
..mih erofeb nrobnogard enorp eht otni peed cigam sih gnihsup
.dnal eht fo srelaeh detcepser-llew dna lufrewop tsom eht gnoma erew ilteuH fo scirelc eht ,dnalemoh ym ni kcab taht dias si tI
,ylteiuq derumrum klofnogard ehT
.ylippah dias redniC
.elcsum dna selacs gnitfihs eht gnileef
,derewsna redniC
”.meht deciton uoy taht desaelp etiuq em sekam ti ,tcaf nI
,deb s'kloftac eht evoba foor htolc tfihsekam desiar a detaerc kcommah A
,oggodneP yb ”sretrauQ s’relaeH ehT“
”.hcum sa flesruoy sserpxe t’nod yllamron uoY“
spahreP' .detcepxe naht regnol gnikat saw yrevocer sih tub
nemodba sih hguorht walc a ekop yltneg dluoc redniC tnedifnoc saw klofnogard ehT
.tsaoC gnitiB eht ssorca tsew raf ,dnalemoh kloftac eht s’tI
selacs sih no htmraw yrd eht htiw xim dniw looc fo srevils tlef klofnogard ehT
”?flesruoy ti od uoy nac ro ,revo uoy pilf ot em
,rood eht gnisolC
”.rehtona ro nosaer eno rof dees fo sgab rof gniksa neeb ev’uoy em dlot yffulF dnA“
”,uoy emalb t’ndluow I“
,sih tsniaga gnisserp hself dna ruf s’regit eht fo thgiew dna htmraw ehT
,dias eb ot dedeen ti kniht t’ndid I“
”.trofmoc emos tsael ta uoy thguorb gnilaeh ym epoh I“
.flesmih denoitisoper eh sa moor teiuq ,delffum eht ni ylduol dednuos senob dna selacs sih morf skcarc tfos ehT
”.redduhs klofnogard a ekam ot syaw era erehT“
,yalpsid lluf ni mrof ytfeh sih
”.rehto hcae ot pu nepo straeh rieht ,ecrof efil erahs sgnieb owt nehW
.slarotcep sih htaeneb selacs etaciled eht hguorht gniliart spit wap mraw eht
,thgil eht debrosba emarf suoreneg s’tac gib ehT
,flesmih esopmoc ot tnemom a koot klofnogard ehT
.syad fo elpuoc tsap eht rof peels esol ot mih gnisuac
.edam redniC taht deb eht otno debmilc dna kcab sih tneb eh sa detnurg hniroT ".thginot
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,nwod tneb eh sa egarevel erom dah regit nedlog eht
,spih sih ot ylleb s’klofnogard eht nwod dekrow eh sa gnixelf smra daorb sih
.ydob sih ni rogiv dnuofwen a esnes ot detrats eh
.deb eht ot dennip yltneg mih gnipeek
,erom ecno rewolf llams eht derujnoc regit nedlog ehT
,noinapmoc sih no nwod thgiew sih desserp yletaciled eh sa
.gur eht otni rehtruf knas eh sa dehgis hniroT
.hniroT ,em s'tI !redniC"
.ytilibapac nwo ym fo egduj eht gnieb tnedifnoc taht ton m’I ?erus ton m’I“
.krow sih no desucof eh sa ,deilper redniC
,mra thgir sih dexelf klofnogard etihw ehT
,rehtegot swap sih debbur redniC
.ynapmoc s’rehto hcae gniyojne htiw tnetnoc
.tcefferetfa toh ylbatrofmoc a dniheb gnivael
,yrecros gnilaeh eht yb thguorb snoitasnes eht htiW
.thgil egnaro eht ni gninihs dna gnitfihs ruf tfos eht
,srewop esoht dleiw ot rewoplliw eht evah uoy fi tuB
.ekove I taht cigam eht tnemgua ot stnenopmoc ym esoohc I tub ,slleps ym hguorht relaeh a ma I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,snibac s'pihs gniylf eht fo eno drawot hguorht deklaw eh sa derednop hniroT
”.noitoved s’dog tsevrah a ekil dnuos seod taht hguohT
.htolcniol tevlev ,nooram a fo gnirevoc eht rof evas
,erdaC elacsthgirB eht tsael ta ro …hsarobrihT taht wonk ton did I
,ylthgils ni nael tac gib eht tlef eh ,dehgis klofnogard eht sA
.snoitan rehto ni si ti naht rehtnamyT ni tnereffid hcum si egairram taht nrael ot dah ev’I
.hA“ ”?ton yeht nac ,rehto eht ot dael ylisae nac eno dna ,deniwtretni era owt ehT“ .deilper redniC
.deneppah tsuj dah tahw fo foorp sa tsehc sih no mlab eht fo htmraw ykcits eht ylno htiw
”.llew sa ssertsid lanoitome tub stnemlia lacisyhp fo srelaeh sa nwonk ylno ton erew ilteuH fo stseirp ehT“
,erab saw ruf s'kloftac ehT
”.hself eht no gnihtoos erom era slleps ym kniht I
,selacs sih hguorht decal cigam fo sdnarts eniF
.ria eht ni gnitfaw sbreh fo stnih tniaf htiw
.neewteb ni elcsum denedrah-elttab eht gnidaenk
,hguoht taebtraeh a retfa dehsinav taeh dna thgil ehT
.pu smra sih desiar eh sa gnitfihs ylleb dna tsehc sih fo klub dna ruf tfos eht
”,truh ot strats gnihtyna fi em lleT“
”.mih dnuora luferac erom eb ot deen od I spahreP
.noitacided dna gniniart fo sraey deen uoy skram eseht niatbo oT .su fo lla toN“
tnurg eltneg a otni denrut muh peed siH
”.neve ,ot desu m’I naht trofmoc hguone naht erom ebyam spahrep saw
.elzzum sih no ylthgil tser
”?tsehc yvaeh a evah uoY“
swap sih hguorht ecrof hcum oot ylppa ot ton luferac
?taht yb naem uoy od tahW“ .deksa hniroT ”?evoL“
.ilteuH htiw llew ngila I yhw nosaer eht si taht spahreP
”.ot deen t’ndluow I em sllet gnihtemos hguohT
.ecnesse efil gniviecer dna gnivig fo noitarbelec etavirp eht
.eraperp redniC dehctaw eh sa delbmur hniroT ".thgin
,hctah eht desolc eh tnurg a htiW
.htlaeh ruoy fo tnemssessa lareneg a sa llew sa
.hgis llams a htiw dias redniC
”.tsaob ot ekil yllamron ton od I dna
.deotpit hniroT ”?sgnisselb rehto
",flesym trexe I revenehw gnap thgils A"
,thgil mid eht ni yltniaf dewolg ruf egnaro dna maerc thgil siH
.cinut sih eveirter ot togrof osla eh ,sediseb dnA
.elttab ni erif fo stcepsa ssenrah I emit eht fo tsoM“
.tsiom teg ot nageb swap sih dna
”.dneirf ,enif si tahT“
”.hcaorppa ot tsurt nac I taht eno era uoy tub
tnaw uoy oD .kcab ruoy no uoy dah I fi reisae eb ll’tI
.hguoht ,tnasaelpnu ton saw tI
.kcab sih nwod kcab deliart swap sih sa ylizal yaws liat s’redniC dehctaw hniroT .yltfos dias eH
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
.tfos deedni dna yzoc saw deb ehT
.reyarp a derettum eh sa seye sih desolc eh ,rehtegot swap egral sih gnibbuR
.niaga tsehc sih htiw tcatnoc ni emoc swap mraw eht tlef eh sa
.ereh regnorts neve deciton eh taht tnecs yhtrae ,tniaf eht
…tsae tuo dlroW eurT ehT ni kcab neve deppihsrow nalc ym taht dog a si ilteuH ,neht lleW“ .regit yrrebwarts eht ta pu gnicnalg ,derewsna hniroT
”.relaeh ruo laets ot elba eb thgim tsuj yeht diarfa m’I
.gninethgit spih s’hniroT no pirg eltneg sih
.enips dna kcab daorb s’klofnogard eht no slatep gniremmihs eht gnirettacs
.ria eht derrits mih evoba ydob egral eht sa
.cigam dna hcuot sih ot esnopser ni xelf meht gnileef dna selcsum gnorts eht otni gnisserp ,setulg s’klofnogard eht otni gid ot nageb swap siH
.tsehc s’klofnogard eht no eltneg swap sih
.resolc klofnogard eht gninokceb
.seidemer larutan no deiler yltsom ew dnalemoh ym ni kcaB“
,gur hsulp eht ni deirub tuons sih htiW
.rood nedoow ,dlo eht no yltfos dekconk eh
.ereh tser mih tel ot tnaem yllaer tac eht fi enilef eht nedrub ot tnaw t’ndid eH
.ti dnuora elcsum eht gnidaenk
”.ytilitref dna evol fo sseddog eht osla si ehS
.seog gnilaeh fo tra rieht sa raf sa laog eht s’taht ,scirelc ynam roF“
,taht dnim t’ndluow I“
,klofnogard eht ot citoxe ylthgils saw kloftac a fo tnecs ehT
rudatsI“ .deilper hniroT
.ylyhs gnilims ,deilper redniC ".dnim
.scirelc etabilec esoht tsniaga osla era uoy emussa I
”.laem doog a retfa yllaicepsE
”.hguoht siht wonk od I“
,peels ot mih llul ot gninetaerht erew regit yrrebwarts eht fo snoitom eltneg ,htooms ehT
.relaeh eht yb denrael saw ydob sih sa desopxe leef klofnogard eht edam tI
.mih dniheb yllufyalp deyaws liat sih sa
,elpoep nwo ruo era ew taht wohs ot si liat on evah oT
?irkaS …utsI“ .deksa regit ehT
”.dog ym fo sreppihsrow dnif I netfo ton s’ti dna
,pu dekrep srae siH
.emit retsam ew ecneitap hguorhT
”?dog ruoy ot eud siht si ro noitanilcni lanosrep ruoy tsuj siht sI“