ygolohtna eht ni yrots siht dnif nac uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.pleh deen t’nod I“
.txen eht neht dna
.peels ot elcric a otni delttes ti sa nogard eht rehtob t’ndid tnuh dnuob-cirbaf deliaf ehT
.roolf enots eht tsniaga kcilc swalc reh tsel
.llaw eht ni eloh a otni deraeppasid taht liat ynniks eht fo espmilg a thguac ylno dna ,decnuop ehS
…dna ,seldeen gnittink ,spac nep ,sraj fo sdil
.srae dna seye reh esu ot deen d’ehs os
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,reh ta dekool enoyreve woh saw tI
,flesti derenroc dah tsaeb ehT
,ti dniheb eno eht neht
.noitnetta reh rof thguof slriws tnelis eht
.gninetsil m’I swonk yerp ehT
.ylerus ,emac emit eht nehw gnihtemos fo kniht d’ehs dna
,dehs eht reednammoc dluoc ehS
.sdraug fo lluf eltsac gib a ni evil I
.meht neewteb deggard liat a rof enil suounitnoc a dna sdap yna tuohtiw tub ,sdnah ekil dekool tsomla stnirpwap ehT .skcart
.thgin eht otni deraeppasid tnemevom fo yrrulf a sa tuhs dna nepo degnab wodniw ehT
.erofeb naht rellams neve dekool ti
.redro ni kcab moordeb reh gnittup fo ksat nmelos eht ot flesreh dengiser ehs erofeb edaf ot sevooh gnippolc eht rof detiaw ardnaxelA .dias ehs
,reh gnitib xof elttil eht tuoba yrrow ot dah eram eht taht toN
.gnorw og dluoc ti syaw fo dairym a erew erehT
,yrd oot saw siht tub
eno ynit yletulosba na—nogard a saw tI
.elzzum reh ot yaw sti ekam ot tsehc reh ni yvaeh oot gnuh hturt eht
.dezeens ehs dna eson reh derewoprevo ruf degnis fo keer ehT
.efil ot defoowf pmal sag a dna hctiws eht dekcilf ehS
.laiceps t’nerew yeht tub
.dekcolnu saw sreh gniniojda moor eht dna
.thguac teg ot ton nosaer retaerg neve na htiw won
.ylreporp yawa sehtolc reh tup ehs sa srae detniop reh neewteb delttar saedI
”,uoy eveileb t’nod I“
yrots s’yadoT dna
,moor reh ot kcab gniknils erofeb rood eht tuhs ardnaxelA
.ekirts thgim ehs tnih yna rof reh dekcart seye sti woh dehctaw dna drawkcab pets a koot ehS
”snrocinU eht dna xoF ehT“   yojne esaelP
,dah yeht wonk t’ndid ardnaxelA
”!uoy toG“ .smlap reh ta dekcirp tsur
”,ssenhgiH ruoY ,llew tser nehT“
.flesreh dlot ehs ,sucoF
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.seye eulb yreif dna selacs der-ybur htiw—
;detartnecnoc tub ,niaga tnecs taht saw ereht dna
”!flesym ti od nac I“
!sgniht lla fo ,tar a gnisahC
!nwogthgin reh ylno ni
!deracs eb ot nosaer on evah I
,etisbew s’esahC ta seirots erom neve dnif nac uoY
,ecnetsixe elbatrofmoc erom a deyojne dna
,tfel eht ot skram gard erom erew erehT
.derepsihw ardnaxelA ”,ti peeK“
.pu evag dna detartsurf werg ehs
,esruoc fo ,snenil fo tnaw ni t’nsaw ehS
.esirprus ni pmuj reh gnikam ,moor eht dellif kaerc cillatem A
.nogard eht ot kcab sthgis reh deppans ssih A
,xof dezilivic a sA
!em morf gnipacse ton er’uoY
gninetsil er’uoY
.roolf eht ssorca sniatnuom inim detaerc snoihsuc hcuoc dna
,nosrednA esahC yb ”snrocinU eht dna xoF ehT“ saw sihT
.tsen sti saw siht
;dexaler ydob s’nogard eht neht dna ,dessap tnemom A
.don a htiw dednopser nortam eht litnu stnemom lareves saw tI ”!yawa oG
saw ereht reh dlot gnihtemos tey
.depley ssecnirP eht
moor s’ardnaxelA edistuo yawllah ehT
.thguac gnieb naht gniyfitrom erom neve saw
,yltfos koohs htap eht fo edis thgir eht no hsub A
dehs a ta dedne esahc ehT
.krad eht ni nrecsid t’ndluoc ehs erutaerc emos fo yraipot eht dniheb dekcut
”—ot em ekil uoy dluoW“
.gnihton saw ereht tub
.roolf tsrif eht no saw moor reh lufetarg saw ehs ecno roF
.hcnilf nogard eht edam dnuos eht ;depley ehS
.gnihtolc dereflip eht morf ylbamuserp
—yllufknaht— ytpme saw
.tuo gnihtemos erugif d’ehS
,revelc era sexof tuB
dnuof gnieb sehtolcllams reh fo aedi eht tuB
nosrednA esahC yb
slessat elprup htiw knip dna erutxet thgir eht tsuj t’nerew yehT
,anipluV a dna xof a saw ehs tuB
.srae reh otni knuls erutcurts eht edisni swalc fo gnilbbarcs ehT
;tsud pu derrits tnemevom eht ,llitS
.thgil eht ot detsujda seye reh sa deknilb ehS
,sdnuos yna hctac ot deleviws srae reh ;ezorf ardnaxelA
,ti tuoba thguoht ardnaxelA erom ehT
.rehtona dna ,rehtona neht dna ,pets a koot ehS
.ereht ni gniht a
!sremoolb ym gnilaets ,tar detsalb A
.tesolc reh otni ssot ot yrrac dluoc ehs revetahw pu depoocs ehS
.fo maerd reven dluoc snisuoc gniknits rieht slairetam fo stsen gnikam
.thgieh s’ardnaxelA ot nwod tneb nortam ehT
.ti did sdiamrebmahc eht nehw sa yltaen sa tuo emac reven yeht tub ,meht gnidlof deirt dah ehs
.ssenkrad eht otni deknay saw gnihtolc fo eceip a neht
,tesolc reh fo kcab eht htiw derahs llaw eht dnuof ehS
,snoitareneg ni dah anipluV on tub
,nosrednA esahC yb ”snrocinU eht dna xoF ehT“ si
,esrow llems ot tar a detcepxe ehS
.snedrag eht ta nwod dekool dna wodniw eht ot nar ehS
.peels ot teknalb reh deen t’ndluohs ehS !xis saw ehS
.drib tenretni dna ,relgnarw teehsdaerps
.evael ot fi sa daeh reh denrut dna kcab pets a koot ehS
.os od ot suoregnad oot saw noitautis eht wenk tub
,seltit rieht enirhsne ot nogard a gniyals tuoba no tnew syawla srehtorb reH
…doof emos nogard elttil eht kaens ro
.thgilnoom eht ni htolc etihw fo hsalf lanoisacco eht dna tnemevom fo liart elgnis eht ylno saw erehT
.deksa nortam dlo eht
.tar eht ekil knihT
,thgin ta ,edistuo
.gniyrt fo kcal a rof ton hguoht
”?eno elttil ,rettam eht s’tahW“
;sraet kcab deknilb ehS ”.…s’tI“
:sdoog nettog-lli fo elip sti no regral neve kool ot sgniw sti detlit tI
.htiw gnissem er’yeht ohw ees yeht ecno nur ll’yeht dna retsnom taht walc ll’I esuac‘ ,meht deen neve t’nod I teb I
.dnuof eb ot erehwon saw teknalb eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sgnaf reh htiw tar a thguac dah ehs fi naht esrow htuom reh ni etsat a tfel ti dna
”.em naht erom ti deen uoY“
.hguorht nwolb dah snogard fo elag suoiciv a fi sa rednusa nrot gniddeb dna sehtolc letsap
.woleb snedrag eht ot wodniw eht fo tuo deppoh dna thguoht ehs
.peelsa—ylesiw—erew yeht ro ,ecalap eht ta star rehto on erew ereht spahreP
,noisiv larehpirep reh ni dekaerts tnemevom fo rulb A
.waptoof eht ni reh debbats
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daeR  .zyx.jesahc
.psarg sti fo tuo tpael snrocinu nevow eht sa cirbaf eht otni dekooh swalc ynit stI
tey dna dlrow eht ni retsnom tseiracs eht eb ot desoppus saw sihT
,tsrif-dap dednal pets hcae os ylluferac tperc ssecnirP ehT
lanimirc eht ot dael rehtie dluow liart ehT
tub…htrib elbon hcus fo eno fo gnimocebnu erew stcnitsni rotaderp esoht
;sreward rieht ot gnihtolc eht denruter dna deb reh edam ehS
,dnuora gninnur saw ehS
.tsud fo reyal yvaeh a morf ti gnitcetorp
?rehtom sti saw erehW .tar pmulp a naht reggib on saw ti fi ybab a eb ot dah tI .hO
.tnatropmi ssel enoemos morf laets ot esnes eht dah rO
:emirc eht fo ecnedive htiw gnola
,retirw noitcif evitaluceps a
dekrul taht sretsnom eht lla dehsinab taht
,gnihcraes citnarf reh etipsed ,dnA .deb reh rednu
.tcepser dednamed dna ssecnirP ehT saw ehs tub
,sehtolc reh ot gnulc taht emufrep eht dna tsud dna tsum dnoyeb gnihtemos ,eson reh dellif tnecs A
,erutinruf revo depard htolc htiw ,desunu gnol ,yduts a saw tI
sdoow gnitaludnu eht hguorht gnikcilorf snrocinu dna
;dnim reh ta deggut
kcab sremoolb reh teg dluow ehs ,yltcaxe ,woH .eloh rehtona ro
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.thgir erew yeht wenk ehs
.flesreh ekil nepo eht ni tuo gniklaw ton ,llaw eht gniwollof eb dluohs ti os
;niaga deknilb ehS
,ssecnirP a sa ,xof a sa
.emalf fo tuog trohs a htiw tem saw dna gnikniht tuohtiw ti rof dehcaer ehS ”!teknalb yM“
,tnemevom rof denetsil dna llits doots ehS
,sterces on dedleiy tesolc eht fo srenroc krad ehT .enon erew ereht tub
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
cigam a gniyrrac snroh derediorbme rieht dna
,ytidirca dna htlif dna tor ekil
.devom gnihtemos neht dnA
”,tfeL eht ot esrevinU enO“
.ti ecalp t’ndluoc ehs tub
,yas ot hsiw yeht nehw od sesroh lla yaw eht ni dekcilf rae s’rekaterac reH ”?hO“ ”.gnihton s’tI“
.revelc ylbirret saw ehs tnaem hcihw
.redro na yebo dna noitisop reh tcepser dluow tar eht detbuod ehs
,moordeb reh dnuora decnalg
,roolf eht tsniaga slian ynit
.rotaderp eht sa nees saw ehs
,erauqs tcefrep a otni sserd a gnitteg ta tpmetta htruof eht retfA
yaw gnorw eht tsuj denrut levarg fo eceip tsrif eht nehw reh tih ylno noitautis eht fo ssensuolucidir ehT
.sbmil fo gnitfihs yrehtael a
.sraey dna sraey dna sraey rof eno nees neve dah eno oN
anipluV ardnaxelA ssecnirP ehT
,nees eb ot tnaw t’ndluow tI
,gnihtyna llems ot ytsud oot saw moor ehT
.elag a ni gnilpas a ekil koohs ti
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer
.flesreh dlot ehs !anipluV a ma I
.ainrofilaC fo sretirW doowdeR eht yb dehsilbup
,lworg ekil-tar-nu yrev a htiw tem saw ardnaxelA
;nepo rood eht dekrej ehS
eriomra eht fo tuo delgnad srewarD
.noitartsurf reh delworg ehS
star nommoc eht fo yvne eht erew star laitalap spahreP .detum oot
.ecalp tsrif eht ni tespu siht gnimoceb rof flesreh esitsahc ot emit elpma reh dedroffa tI
.emaceb seitilibissop eht reddas eht