elttil sti ni delriws sthguohT
.xob emag a fo espmilg a
.yppah meht ekam I dna ,em syub dlihc ecin emos tahT
.snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT morf
…tsuj s’tI .gniyas er’uoy tahw etaicerppa …I
”!meht fo eno ton er’uoy tub“
.laiceps eb ot detnaw tsuj I“
”!aaaaaahw …ces a tsuj ,yako
.liat sti dekcilf dna denrut tibbar ehT
.ecnelis otni delttes niaga ecno elsia ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dna ,syadiloH yppaH
.wohemos gnimlac tlef tI
?ton m’I fi tahw tuB“
?laicepS“  ”—saw I thguoht I
.daeh dellif-retseylop
”.stiucric gnikam detrats elpoep erofeb gnol dnuora erew su ekil syot ,gniyas tsuj m’I
.flehs rehtona sdrawot dekrej elosnoc ehT ”?yllaer ,hO“
,ekops elosnoc emag eht ”!ti ecaF“
dlihc emos evig oT
noitnetta werd tahw tub ,sliated gnidnarb dna tra revoc tnarbiv htiw
yot nedoow dna tibbar deffuts rehto yreve htiw gniklat si πPXG noitatSemaG rehto yreve kniht uoy
.dennuts saw tibbar ehT
?pohskroW s’atnaS ni edam gnieb meht ees uoy oD ?selosnoc gnimag
…eb ot em tnaw elpoep tahw eb ll’I erus ton m’I dna
.selas samtsirhC-retfa eht ni pu dekcip eb ll’uoy nehT“
!yot a uoy ekam t’nseoD“
seires eht fo noitpada emag oediv eht m’I“
.em ekil tsuj srehto sseltnuoc
htiw pu dedaol eb ll’I ebyaM
.thgilyks eht hguorht noom eht ta pu dekool tibbar eht ,kcab gniyL
,won thgir nevE .egrevid
.noitcartsid decudorp-ssam a tsuj er’uoY
”!esruoc fO“  ”?emit
.dnalerI morf xoF-hateehC a
,delbane tenretni m’I“  .kcud eht deksa
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY .rekihhctiH flowereW ,flowcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,”,xofoS“ yb ”elsiA
,slaudividni sa rehto hcae dnatsrednu dna
,nwod thgiarts deppord esac citsalp digir ,niht A
.tuo ydob sti gnihsup gniffuts sti
”!elosnoc gnimag a tsuj er’uoY
.gnigakcap rieht dna syot fo swor eht gnihcuot
ta dna ,egar eht lla erew syot latem ,egats eno tA
”.fo edam er’uoy tahw fo esuaceb yot ’laer‘ a fo erom ton er’uoY
,)99.95 PRR( πPXG noitatSemaG eht rof emag a saw tI
”.era uoy ohw wonk ll’yehT .erom uoy tnaw lliw sdik fo tol a taht snaem tsuj
erusnu thgin eht detrats dah tibbar ehT
.ecaf eht ni flesti gnippals ylfeirb srae sti ,dnuora deppihw tibbar ehT
,denrut elosnoc eht
;erofeb siht enod t’nevah I ,yob hO ?huH“
,srehto dna ,yrots siht dnif nac uoY
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
;eromyna edamdnah si gnihtoN“
?laiceps os uoy sekam tahw ,lleW“
thguac dna flehs gnimag eht ta pu dekool ti ,daeh sti gnitliT
ffuts edamdnah emos eb tsum ereht“
,kcabworht ,aiglatsoN
s’taht dnA .em no deyalp semag eht lla morf spilc oediv dna ,stohsneercs
,dab dna doog ,semit nwo ruoy evah ,shtap nwo ruoy levart
”.em sekat pets txen eht erehw ees
teiuq emos evah I nac
seirotcaf ni edam
.kcilc dna lrihw a htiw csid tnetsixe -non a tceje ot deirt tsuj daetsni tub
secneirepxe ruo lla
.raf oot enog evah yam ti gnisnes
.ekil s’ti tahw rednow I …ti ni em htiw ereht tuo emag a s’ereht ,oS“
yoT ehT“ saw sihT    ”...ekil
,rorrim a otni gnikool saw ti ekil revoc eht ta dekool
.elor sti deyalp dah ti gnileef
.syot citsalp saw ti emit rehtona
,pu gnileehw ,dehcaorppa kcud nedoow eht ylnO
.uoy yub lliw enoemos ;eno tfos ,yrrow t’noD“
.meht neewteb leehw ot deirt kcud ehT
.stsixe ylerab taht doirep a pu gnimaerd er’uoY“
”?em syub ydobon dna seog dna semoc samtsirhC fi tahW
.pu tas ti elihw a retfA
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ekops tibbar revoc eht ”,haeY“
,kcud eht dias ”,yrroS“
,meht yb ylno deyalp dna moordeb s’enoemos ni eb ll’I ebyaM .semag erutnevda/noitca ro ,strops ,gnithgif
,elbat eht otno flehs sti ffo depmuj πPXG noitatSemaG eht ,taht htiW
”…rehtona ro mrof eno ni detsixe syawla s’ti ,ylbaborp ,haeY“
”.decudorp-ssam lla er’ew
.evah dluow ti ,yrc dluoc ti fI
.netsilg ot demees seye citsalp ynihs sti
.revoc sti gniwohs ,thgirpu flesti dellup yldrawkwa esac eht ”…yako …yako m’I“
,dlrow taht otni tuo og ew tnemom eht tub ,emas eht lla tuo trats thgim ew si tniop ym
.rae sti ot dehcatta llits lebal dna gat sti
.neppah lliw tahw swonk ssendoog ,emoh thguorb dna thguob m’I ecno tub
.em syub laiceps enoemos epoh I“
,sgnidliub dna steerts htiw detniap potelbat nedoow eht no nwod ylivaeh tas tI
era ereht ;ton m’I .euqinu saw I thguoht I
.ni ekat ot tol a si siht …tsuj s’tI“
…tuB“  ”.fo trap a er’uoy
”!uoy fo htob ,tser a ti evig ,hO“  ”…fi tahW
.sllod gar tnuoc ot tnaw uoy sselnu – detsixe ev’yeht sa gnol sa hcum ytterp rof
?uoy deksa ohw ,lleW“
,daeh sti derewol tI
”—evah htob uoy ,kool woN“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.uoy seulav ohw enoemos dnif lliw uoY
.srae hsulp sti ta dellup ylsuovren tibbar eht
”?noitasrevnoc tcaxe siht evah
ll’uoY .sruoy yleuqinu dna
dna pu deddap tibbar deffuts ehT ”?tahw…“ .tibbar A
taps evah dluoc πPXG noitatSemaG eht ”!ahP ?edamdnaH ?euqinU
”.gniht fo tros taht ,syot elitcat
.yltcefrep eno deffuts eht detcelfer tibbar eht fo egami ehT
!em wonk t’now yeht tub ,si ’egami‘
,tibbar yot eht dias ”,epoh I ,hO“
.dlrow eht revo lla delbmessa dna dengised erew em fo strap tnereffiD
”.uoy ot ralimis yllaicifrepus
.duht yvaeh a htiw meht ediseb gnidnal
eb yam ereht tuo ynam woh fo sseldrager
dna epoh si od nac I lla esoppus I
”.ces a rof ereh nwod emoC ?lraC ,yeH“
,kaeps ot deirt ynnub eht ”…tuB“  ”.xa11.208 EEEI iF-iW
.revoc eht no retcarahc eht saw
.elsia til ylmid eht detaemrep ecneliS
,thgilyks eht morf nwod gnimaerts thgilnoom yb
.ti no elbbin ot dedneterp dna torrac hsulp porp a pu dellup tibbar eht ”…sseug …I“
ygolohtna syadilwoH yppaH eht ni
”.tuo dnats nac I yaw on s’erehT .laiceps ton m’I
”.secneirepxe tnereffid evah lliw emag emas eht gniyalp elpoep nevE
,kooL“ .noitnetta sti niager ot tpmetta etarepsed a edam elosnoc ehT
”.ecar namuh eritne eht fo tnemeveihca lacigolonhcet fo nogarap a m’I
.troppus rof aelp tsenrae na ni drawrof denael dna kcud eht ot denrut tibbar eht ”…tuB“
,semag-evas euqinu htiw dellif eb lliw evird drah BT 4.1 yM .ylimaf elohw eht yb deyalp
.tibbar eht ot pu deleehw
taht si yas ot gniyrt s’ti kniht I tahW“
.kcahw a htiw elbat eht otno gnippals
.tibbar eht drawot daeh sti detator dna
.noitisop suoiverp sti ot denruter yllaudarg elosnoc eht
.ksilebo citsalp kcalb eht no gniknilb detrats sthgil deR
sleehw nedoow no kcud nedoow detniap a ”,esruoc fO“  ”.yppah
.ffo denrut ecnis gnol dah sthgil tnecseroulf daehrevo ehT
”!sseneuqinu emos ,ereht tuo
!sraey derdnuh a revo llew rof seirotcaf ni edam neeb evah syoT
dna VT moor gnivil eht rednu eb ll’I ebyam ro
”!hpmH .od I ekil gnikam ruoy otni tup erac dna evol eht evah t’nod uoY
,don ydob-lluf kciuq a htiw dna
.saw ti ,yaw a ni rof
ylno til saw enecs eht ,sngis tixe derettacs emos morf edisA
.niatrecnu erom neve saw won dna
?t’nod yeht fi tahw tuB“  ”.htiaf evah tsuJ
,saw I thguoht I tahw eb ton yam I“
,thgis fo tuo kcab deleehw kcud ehT
)emag oediv eht( lraC
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,yrotcaf a ni edam neeb evah yam I ,mre ,kooL“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
tuoba slaiceps samtsirhC ees uoy oD
neeb evah syot deffuts ,esruoc fo ,dnA
”!thgin yreve siht od uoY“
ym tahw wonk ll’yehT“
,elbat omed a no thgirpu tas tibbar deffuts enol a ,ssenkrad-imes eht nI
.elsia yot eht no delttes thgiN  ,xofoS yb ”elsiA yoT ehT“
,tnelis saw πPXG
,flehs eht no noitisop sti sdrawot kcab devom ylmlac
.niaga pu ekops πPXG noitatSemaG eht ,emihc a htiw ,neht dnA
,lleW“  ”?’ffuts yot‘ ni devlovni teg t’nac I ,cinortcele m’I esuaceb tsuj oS !tahW“
.evah meht yalp ohw elpoep eht secneirepxe eht ot derapmoc gnihton
.yawa kool ot demees tibbar deffuts ehT
,uoy syub yllanif dlihc emos nehw
”?siht lla wonk uoy od woH“
.kcals eht pu dekcip kcud ehT
noitatSemaG eht ,snaf gnilooc sti rof tpecxE  ”.yoj emos
.tniop gnilles a sa syot nedoow gnikam ni sesilaiceps taht dnarb a fo trap m’I neve tuB“
…seires regral a fo trap gnieB .yako s’ti …s’tI“
sruoy eb lliw evah htob uoy ecneirepxe eht
,xofoS yb ”elsiA yoT ehT“
,relevart wollef ruoy