,seiromem hguorht gniggiD ".sdnaW
".sehtolc ycnaf ro sroloc thgirb ni doog kool d'I kniht t'nod I
".ti ot ni sevig tesnus tub
,gnimoc erew uoy em dlot mom ruoY"
,gnirepsihw-egats
,sreffo ehs "?neht ,yteixnA"
".gniht-taoc rieht no srednamalas eht fo kcalb eht rof tpecxe wolley-
ecnatsissa laicnanif rieht naht
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.hcum taht wonk I os
,seunitnoc dna ,eno yb eno ,revo sdrac eht spilf ehS
.tsewhtroN cificaP eht ni rotide dna rohtua na
,naem I --ot tnaw t'nod I"
.retaw fo sehsalps elttil dnA"
,ria fo htaerb a tuo ffup I   .gnimlehwrevo
.detnaw uoy woh desserd uoy fi
?thgir ,gnihtemos ro eriuqs a ekil si egap A" ,yrt I
leef dluoc ksat llams a hcus woH .kniht I ,ddO
,gnirumrum erofeb ,detreva seye dna talf srae
.ecnatpecca tnatculer reh neht dna
.shgual regdab eht
.drac dnoces eht ta kool I ,denetsahc suhT
,reh htiw hgual I
.nwo ym no seye dnik ,sksa ehs
:loof eht s'ereht
".gniog teg ot ygrene noitavitca fo tnuoma reporp eht sdeen tI
".siht fo tuo tog I tahw htiw tespu m'I yas t'nac ,llitS"
.trihs ym naht rethgirb si kcoms tuo-dehsaw reh neve ;cinut ycnaf on
,sgnihsaw sseltnuoc yb ssenbard otni rehtruf dedaf
".esle gnihtemos od ot tnaw t'ndid uoy yas ot detrats uoY
"?revo tfel llits sdnaW fo egaP eht fo tib A"
,ot evah t'nod uoY"
,elbat eht no smra reh gnidlof
,em ot srucco thguoht A
?lliw ni sa ygrenE"
.mom ym morf dedeen I tahw s'taht ezilaer I
- sgniht diputs esoht lla
.revo semit net dellik
,eunitnoc dna don neht ,etatiseh I ".krow
- tuo taht derugif reven ev'I
".uoy no doog kool d'tI
,edins ro tnalutep naht rehtar dnik sdnuos ehs ,llitS
- detnaw reven I emarf daorb a revo depard sehtolc ygnid - em dnA
,naem I --dekool yehT"
".gnihtemos morf yawa gnicaf lla era serugif yehT"
.htaerb ym dleh I
.gnieerga ylpmiS .egas ron gnimrifnoc rehtien tub ,sdon regdab ehT ".htworg
suoigatnoc era noitceffa fo sdrow dna hgual dehsabanu ehT
.yhw rednow dna ,gnihton yas I
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
".sseug I ,dnim ym no s'tI
ssenwols lausac a htiw elbat eht no pu ecaf meht syal dna
.tnelis ,niaga don I
,srae ym ni lleweraf reh htiw ,nehT
dna taorht ym raelc I   .flesmih tac eht sa hgih sa hcae
.gniyned on ,trihs ycnaf a s'tI"
.wolley dna der dna neerg dna eulB
,yrevA ,yaw elbissop tseb eht ni siht naem I
;smaebnus noonretfa ni setom htiw moor thgirb a
.sroloc bard lla raew uoy tuB
,dnoces a rof etatiseh I ".pets
".erohs eht no ecalp sih ot dengiseR
"?meht dnuora pu gnimoc retaw sI"   ".haeY"
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,dad dlot t'nevah llits I tuB"
"?taht od eno dluow yhW"
,eninimef dna enilucsam
.sdrac eht ot gnikaeps
",em ot uoy tnes mom ruoY"
.drac eht ta gnikool peek I ,gniddoN
.reh rof yltnereffid dekrow dlrow eht sehsiw ehs tcepsus I
.gnitalpmetnoc ro gnitagitsevni er'yeht ekil skool yehT ?mmh ,gniniart nI"
- seltit ro elpoep retfa deman sdrac esehT"
.ih yas ,yb pots ot diarfa eb t'noD
,cirbaf dehsaw-revo eht ot ti gnidloh retemomreht reh no pilc eht ees nac I .sdon regdab ehT
.eerht tsrif eht fo pot no talf ti gniyal
sgniht esoht lla reh llet I
.tey nwohs s'ehs naht ytirohtua erom dna
".taob eht fo mottob eht hguorht debbats neeb ev'yeht ekil ,thgirpu
,llikrevO ?ti t'nsI"
.niaga sdon ehS   ".mhmM"   "?emoh morf yawA"
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.thgirb yats seye reH
.esoppus I ,tuo gnimoC"   "?tib hcihw tuobA"
,epahs tnereffid A
".tnemom a rof ti tuoba kniht dna tis uoy neht dnA ?uoy era
"?doolb ees uoy oD"
,drac tsrif eht ot kcab gniddon
.erom drac eht tuoba kniht I elihw
.drac eht ot txen wap a stes ehS ".retteb
.flesym fo erus erom
.txen eht neht dnA
,kaeps ot htuom reh snepo dna sdrac eht selffuhs ehS
,yas I ",gnitrats reven
.ruf ym htiw og t'nseod tI
".on ro sey yas tsuj nac
.tuons tnulb ym pu rehtruf sessalg gnigdun ,resolc nael I
:esruoc fo ,yaw tsednik eht ni taht naem I" .syas ehs
,eunitnoc dna ,keep ot pu drac tsal eht tfil I "--eht ekil
.leef I tahw rof drow gnorw eht si regnA
"?gninrael toN"   ".desrever tuB"
.gnilims ,syas regdab eht ",snoitalutargnoC"
.gnikniht em sah tahw si gniht cinut rieht tub
.spahrep ,snoitaerc siH"
".taht ekil nees eb ot tnaw t'nod I"
.sdrow ym morf tcartsid ot elttil seod taht
"?yas ot riaf eb taht dluoW"
.tem ev'I sgod eht fo yna ekil kool t'nseod ti hguoht
hgiew t'nod yeht ekiL"
dna dnik si hgual reH   ".taht tsap teg ot woh no sthguoht yna evah I fi ksa ll'uoy woN
.sikahk nrow-llew eht od roN
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.sregnif reh ni revo ti gninrut dna
,elbat llams a revo smool regdab ehT
noitca dna noissaP
.sdrac eht ta nwod serutseg dna
.ti htiw tuo nwolb elggurts taht gnileef
".rolesnuoc a htiw
,kced eht fo redniamer eht htiw gnilddif swap krad
.uoy knahT .thgirla s'ti ,oN"
,dne eht ot deit gab a htiw skcits esoht fo eno evah yehT
"?ees uoy od seno lluf ynam woH
.sdrow rof elggurts I sa gnippid elzzum
"?gnivirts eht si erehw oS
.detapicitna I naht lufgninaem erom egami na
.ylluferac guh eht nruter I
.eno lacitsym a naht tneb ylrehtom erom a fo s'ehs dna
"--dedeen I wonk t'ndid I
,stnemeergasid gnitnuom ym revo gnikaeps
.tcatnoc eye gnikam naht rehtar swap reh gnihctaw ro
.sdrac nwod-edispu tuoba kniht I os
,gniworg gniht ylno eht si dnaw ehT .dnaw eht sseug I...hu ,ehT
",gnihtemos teg oT"   .sdon ehS
.ecnayonna fo stnih tsrif eht htiw gnola hsulb A
.sdrac fo kcats gniniamer eht ot nwod sdon dna
.em rof sehsinif ehs
.ees ot em rof revo drac eht snrut dna gurhs elttil a sevig ehS
.noitnetta eht ward ot senil era erehT
.dnuora deppilf semoceb taht ,desreveR"
".em fo tuo tol a koot sihT"
.esiwrehto ereht stis
.retemomreht ydnac ssalg a yb
.ylwols erom tnemetats eht etelpmoc I dna
".yvan no srewolf htiw eulb dna neerG
",yrevA ,yad ruoy tuoba em lleT"
.gninnigeb eht ta ereh m'I esuaceB"
,nerdlihc gniwonk fo esnes eht ni
.selor decrof ta noitartsurf eht
".os ro nezod a fo tuo eerht ebyam ,owT"
,mom ym tuoba reh llet I
.gniracnu dna desucof ,tfos dna drah
.ylwols sdon namow redlo ehT
,emoh elpmis a ni moor gnivil elpmis a tsuj ,separd ruolev krad ro
".tuo su sraew sgniht tuoba gnikniht tsuj nehw ,lla ta esicrexe deen ew rednow a s'tI .taht seod tI"
,gniltsirb sreksihw
.nethgirb seye reH
,dda dna resolc ni nael I ".sgniht
.gninnirg em evah dna
.retemomreht taht gnilriwt dna gnihcuols
tnemom a rof ecnelis ni tis eW
"?thgir ,tnemtnioppa taht evah uoy dna ,mom ruoy dlot ev'uoY"
.sarkahc dna slatsyrc fo dlrow maerd emos ni ton
,erohs mlac a ,yks krad a
".txen eht gnikat ,taht retfa dna
.lacitsym gnihtemos sa
.kniht I ,mom ym naht ylrehtom eroM
,sgnileef ym fo seceip dna stib reh gnillet tuoba
.kcab sih ni ruof ro eerhT
",rood eht ni emac uoy nehw dah uoy tahw tog uoY"
.yletinifed ,egnahC .sey ,htaeD
,hguoht ,regdab eht nI
,sgniht no krow ll'ew skniht ehs wonk I .t'now I"
"?thgink a spleh ohw enoemoS
.edisni pu tnep ygrene taht lla gnivael
.eerf rof elbaliava skrow lareves dna tuo skoob ruof sah ehS
,kcen ym fo kcab eht ta ffucs I ".esoppus
,rethgiarts elttil a pu tis neht ,don I   .shgual ehS ".erutuf
?ecivda rof em ot uoy tnes ehs dnA .thgirlA"
".neht ,drac driht ehT" ,pu kaeps I
.sgninaem repeed sti no troper a gnitirw ton er'uoY .koob a ton s'tI"
,nirg dna kcab srae ym yal I
,ecivda uoy evig ot gniog m'I fi dnA
.hguoht ,gnihtemos hgiew llits elpoep ehT
"?desrever ekil ti s'tahW"
,sgurhs ehS   "?emit a ta enO
.seye ym llor I   ".em llet uoY"
.won ,nwot ni er'uoY"
krow reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
-"   ".wolley ,roloc
"?ecivda ym tnaw uoy ,woN
".noisicedni htiw flesruoy gnillik peek dluoc uoy ro
,erom ecno elbat eht ot fles llud ym morf pu kool I
,pets tsrif taht gnikat si no desucof m'I tahw sseug I nehT"
.rettam taht rof ,lla ta rO
.dluow uoy kniht I"
".llits ykcits eb ll'yeht hguoht ,swollamhsram edam neve I"
.pu worg meht nees gnivah ni
.lliw yeht erehw og snoitasrevnoC" ,shgual ehS
",stun si mom ruoY"
.tnemssarrabme elpmis htiw decalper noos era esehT
.selkcuhc ehs ",hguone riaF"
.hguorht ti klat ot ecnahc a dnA" .stressa ehs
.efil tuoba gninraeL"
.neht ,xis eht ot evitanretla na s'ti ebyaM"
.ecnelis ysaenu na ot ffo liart I nehw syas ehs ",woN"
,riahc eht morf pu flesym revel I
.reh ta nworf I   "?uoy t'noD
.kcab srae ym yal I
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
".elpmart ot naem t'ndid ,yrroS"
- tuo llaf sdrows ehT"
.llat yletanutrofnu leef I
"?taht ta gid ot tnaw uoy oD"
- uoy nihtiw gnihtemos ro uoy
.sevlesmeht edisni sgnidne eht fo lla tog ydaerla ev'yeht dna
.stnerap morf yawa gnieB
.ecneirepxe devil ni ylrehtoM
,nediw elims s'regdab eht gniees tub
...retaw eht ,noziroh eht
,thgiarts pu tis ot em teg ot hguone em skcohs egami ehT
,gnihtemos ro ekal a ssorca deirref gnieb dlihc a dna namow a yas ot tnaw I ,llew...a
.ereht gnidnats tsuj er'yeht
.dik ,ecivda s'tahT"
.taob eht ni seloh eht gniggulp er'yeht ebyaM
.elpoep tuoba semitemos er'yeht
.hgual I   "?od sdrows od tahW
,doog kool d'uoy kniht I"
,ereht eb yam ygrene ehT
?meht fo hcae morF"
,gninrael si
,gnihton tnaem taht
.ysmulc gnileef wap
.sretlaf elims yM
.gnihtemos niag oT"
,ruf trohs htiw sdeerb esoht fo eno ,god a s'ereht ,llew ,yakO"
?tnerapsnart os I mA
reh fo noitasnes a s'ti ;gniht elbisiv a ton s'tI
.yrtsimehc ni ekiL"
",em rof boj ym gniod er'uoY"
.egaP eht no sucof
,ecnetnes a fo gninnigeb eht sa ti dnetni I ".ees I kniht I"
.ssentsenrae ylno esnes I
.uoy tuoba s'drac siht ebyaM
.yldniknu ton gnilims
.sdrac gninethgiarts
bmud ,gib A .xommul A .elgnatcer A
drac eht ta gnirats em
.syaw nwo ruo ni ecneserp rieht gnigdelwonkca htob erew ew ekil tlef tI
,reilrae flesruoy thguac uoY" .yltnetni
.kcen sih ni eno ,rae sih ni enO"
.elbat eht ot ezag reh snruter regdab ehT
,gnihtyna naht deredliweb erom
,sdrac dna elbat eht ,regdab ehT
,noitome hcum ooT
.dias tsuj I tahw s'taht tuB"
,ereh no gniog tol a eb ot dnuob s'ereht dna
,rumrum dna elggig a elfits I ".kcab
.democleW .detaicerppa
.daeh reh sekahs dna shgual ehS
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,dad ym tuoba reh llet I
si yrots s’yadot dna
.ygrene dekcolb dna slatsyrc oT
.steews fo sllems ehS
.eb dluoc lla yeht rO
.ereh em tnes mom ym yhw ylbaborp s'taht ezilaer I
.lacitsym ssel raf dna yhtrae eroM .kniht I
.xis eht fo krow eht naht rehtar ,nwod dennip
"?thgir ,htob ot yaw ruoy no er'uoy ekil sdnuos ti ,lleW"
".rettam taht rof ,uoy rof dnA
.flesym ot neve ,suoibud dnuos I .reffo I
.flesym ot neve ,suoibud dnuos I ".os kniht I"
,drawrof detnac llits sreksihW
,sgninnigeb rof
.denetfos sah ezag reh ,seye ym nepo I nehW
.noitca hguone ton
"?rednegsnart er'uoy tahT"
.krims ym gninruter ,sehsinif ehS ".flesruoy
".thguoht I naht retal yaw s'tI
.yas I ",egelloC"   "?won yhW"
".sey ,gnihtyna hgiew
.elbat eht revo ni nael I dna
".pets eht gnikat reve tuohtiw aedi eht ni seloh noillib a gnikop dna tuo gnimoc ta gnirats em ekiL .xis eht ekiL"
,tnemom eht ni devil ecneirepxE
,snoitatcepxe ot yrartnoC
.tsael ta ,egaP eht naht eroM
".gnihsals dna gnikcah yldrah s'tI .doolb on tuB
.ytinilucsam no pirg nori sih dna mih fo ma I deifirret woh dna
.swap tfed ni kced torat eht fo redniamer eht snethgiarts dna
.detcepxe I naht erom saw sihT
".sdrows fo tol a s'tahT"
".riaf s'taht ,sey...I"
,ydob tnereffid a
".der si kaolc sih hguohT" .timda I ",oN"
,dda dna elims yrw a evig I ".sgniht
.drow eht fo esnes tseurt eht ni
.drac tsrif eht ta pat dna
".em ot elbartenepmi sleef tI"
.krow wohs si yeht tahw tuB
.si ti sa ,derit ytterp gnitteg m'I
".yas lliw rolesnuoc eht tahw tuo dekaerf llits m'I dna
.sretrats rof ,nwod edispu s'eno siht ,lleW"
?eh t'nsi ,daed llits s'eh tub - feiler a s'taht
toraT eht si siht ecnis ,oS"   ".sdeen ro
,knI dirbyH ta sa llew sa
,spets esoht gnikat peek dluoc uoY
"?spahrep ,gninrael htiw gnihtyna gniod ton...toN"
.desserdda yletarebiled os gnieb ecnaraeppa ym ta ,skeehc ym ot hsulf neddus a s'erehT   "?taht s'yhW
,snoitseuq eht ,pu-sserd eht
.xim doog a s'tI .ylsuoireS"
.sruoh wols gnillot kcolc A
.niaga sdrows eht tnuoc I
".retaw eht ni wol s'taob eht fo kcab eht ,kooL
.doolb wohs - stius yna ni
,esoht ot erats ym evom I
.wonk t'nod I"
,mihw a no ksa dna ylregae don I
".ygrene eht evah t'nod I"   .gnitiaw
,nirg ym snruter ehS
,detlits si egaugnal ym ,llitS
.neppah ot tey snoitaerc eb dluow seno rehto esoht ,thgirpu erew drac eht fI"
"!ygrene noitavitcA"   ".noisiced on tub
".eciton uoy gniht tsrif eht em llet dna ,kooL
.rof tiderc reh evag I naht mom ym ot erom ylbaborp s'ereht taht ezilaer I
.ria gnineve eht otni tuo
.revo denrut ,desrever
.ti mrifnoc ot hctaw ym kcehc I
.sehtolc ycnaf dna sroloc thgirb ni sserd ot tnaw t'nod uoy yas t'ndid uoY" ,seunitnoc ehS
.regdab eht ta erats I
".taht ekil ffutS .elpoep lliK .bats dna tuC"
elbat eht drawot nwod deggut kcoms reh fo eveels trohs eht
"--yeht ebyaM" ,sdon ehS
,drac eht ot nwod srumrum ,sdon ehS
.em htiw gnola gniddon
,em ot esolc ni snael ehS
- gnidaer drac torat eht
,nwad eht ta gniratS"
.ksa I "?meht dniheB"
.em ot dna sdrac eht tsap skool dna
,egdelwonk seirrac eciov reH ".neppah
.ebyam ,msicitsym s'mom ym ot noitcaer A
.ti epacse dluoc I flesti drac eht morf ecnatsid emos gniniag yb fi sa
.yltnatiseh yas I ",oS"
.trihs ym fo meh eht htiw gnilddif flesym hctac I
.krad hctip si taob eht fo mottob ehT .redrah kool I
.gnihtyreve er'yeht ,ereh ,loof ehT"
- gnitterf tneps I emit hcum woh fo esuaceb s'ti ,won gnihtemos fo gninnigeb eht ta m'I fI" ,gniunitnoc ,gurhs I   "?os woH"   ".neht ,esnes erom sekam tahT"
.nwo ym rof gninraey eht nwod gnipmat dna
,syenruoj lla fo gninnigeb eht tA
dnah dereffo ym sessapyb ehS
,detrevni sgninaeM
"?eb dluow noitseuq txen ym tahw sseug uoy naC" ,shgual ehS
.terces a no ni uoy tel ll'I"
,dootsrednu leef osla I   .tac
,roloc evilo na s'tI
,shturt gnikaeps fo esnes eht ni ylrehtoM
pets tsrif taht ekat
.sgniht gniworg lla s'tI
".nam doog yrev a ekam t'nod uoy tub
,eunitnoc ot snetsah ehS ".dluow
.elims edins a morf flesym niartser ot evah I   ".dekcolb tub
.seunitnoc ehs ",llitS"   .gniddon
".enecs eritne eht ni neerg htiw gniht ylno eht
".emit rehtona rof s'taht tub
.erugif eht tcepsni dna esolc ni nael I
"?doow eht hguorht gniog er'yeht ekiL ?debbatS"
.sdrow rof gnilbmuf ,rumrum I
.eromyna yas ot deen t'nseod ehs ezilaer I dnA
,doohdlihc morf ffuts taht lla reh llet I .reh llet I oS
,ytilibissop yreve gnitagitsevni yb gnillats saw I fi oS"
.sgurhs ehS   "?esopruP
kcoms reh morf retemomreht eht gnippilcnu ,sdon regdab ehT
.wap reh fo erutseg elttil a htiw no em segru dna selims ehS
hgual yldnik a tuo stel neht ,kcab serats ehS
".yawyna ,tuo meht teg ot hsur a ni smees eno on tub ,llet t'nac I"
.ecafrus sti no dekcats yltaen tser sdrac lufroloc fo kced A
".sdrows eht ni dehsdoolb yna t'nsaw ereht dias uoy thguoht I" ,eganam
.drow eht fo esnes laretil eht ni tespu
.elddim eht dnuora guh mrif a em sevig dna
sdrac denrutrevo eht revo spitregnif gnihsurb ,don I
,sdrows llits er'yehT"
- redneg tuoba gniklat
...ot ydaer er'uoy won dnA
.nwod esolc noisserpxe reh esnes I ,siht tA
,tsael ta ,rehtom ym naht ylrehtom eroM
".enim ton ,sdrow reH"
.si tnemetats taht eurt woh tsuj gnizilaer ,gurhs I ".si
"?ti yas ot tnaw t'nod uoy tuB"
.hgual I ",hguone eruS"
,tnorf sih no talf dial enilef A .neT
.krow wohs sdrowS .sloot er'yeht tub
.kcab s'erugif suomynona eht fo tuo gnikcits sdrows eht tnuoc I
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”looF ehT“
.yllufyalp syas ehs ",tsrif ti dias uoY"   "?'eh' ,tiaW"
,sgninaem esoht fo emos no pu gnikcip er'uoY
.reffo dluoc yeht ssengnignoleb tahw dna
,kced eht fo pot eht morf drac rehtona spils ehs sa erus sregnif reh
.nigeb I ",llik ot...oT"
".ni meht evael ot tseb s'ti ebyaM
.haeY"   "?naem uoy ,sdrac ehT"
,tnemom a kniht dna tis I"
.noitavitca eht hcaer ti gnittel ton si
.yrdnual ytrid fo ssem a ekil skool noil niatnuom A
,revo deppit dna nwod-edispu ,serugif nwod-edispU
tsuj ti ;txen eht ot erehps eno morf pmuj ot nortcele na rof ygrene hguone eb ot sah ereht tub ,ykrod s'tI
.sgniht ralugnis tuo kcip ot gniyrt
.retteb si gnitavitca spahrep rO .gniod rof
.yltnerappa ,eciohc yM
citegrenE"   "--drac eht ni wolley s'gnihtyrevE"
,thgin eht sesahc nwad ekil sleef syawla tI .kniht I ,nwaD"
,ecnadiug elbatrofmocnu eht
.yltnerappa ,eciohc yM
,wap a pu sdloh ehS   "--llits er'yeht tuB"
,gnitagitsevni neeb evah
.smrifnoc ehs ",ecitoN"
.em dlo eht eb dluoc ti rO" .elbmum I
.gnilims ,pu skool ehs hcihw ot ,hgual I
".no gniog yllautca s'tahw em llet ot deen ot gniog er'uoy
,sredluohs dehcuols ym otni nwod hcnuh I
".ees uoy tahw em llet tsuJ"
"?rehto hcae llik elpoep yhw em gniksa uoy erA
.htworg gnitagitsevnI
".erofeb - gnitrats ton dna
.noissap fo roloc ehT"
.sdnaW fo egaP eht
,esuap a retfa stimda ehs ",naelc emoc ll'I"
.llits dloh I ,deltratS
.regdab eht ot wap ym reffo dna
.flesruoy fo stecaf tsuj er'yeht ebyaM"   "?loof eht m'I oS"
,raelc neve s'retaw eht ,kooL
"?loot a era sdrows eht yas tsuj ew nac
”looF ehT“ saw sihT
.seye ym esolc I
.on ro sdrac ,tuoba klat nac ew erom stol s'erehT
.tsenrae si elims reh dna ,syas ehs ",citeoP"
,ti yas ot tnaw t'nod I ,naem I .oN"
,hguoht ,ylsuoireS"
,nirg a htiw retemomreht eht ta spat ehS ".yats
erom derettam fles nwo ym gnimoceb taht gnidiced dna loohcs rof gnivael tuoba reh llet I
.niaga ,elims tfos tahT ".dik
,ton esruoc fo ,on :yas neht
.krow eht si yenruoj ehT
,arehtet nat nay sdrac sward ehS
.suoicaps dna thgirb si moor eht
"?won gnihtemos fo gninnigeb eht ta uoy era dnA" .sdon ehS
,ytfif naht redlo eb t'nac ehS
,oot ,kced eht ni sthgink era erehT"
?ebyam ,raeb a - egaP sihT"
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,erutseg a htiw drac eht ot nwod kcab noitnetta ym sediug ,gninnirg llitS ".rettam
,sdnaW fo egaP eht ekil ,uoy oS
.oot ,xim doog a er'uoY
".gniog peek dna txen eht ekat ot evah tsuj I neht dna ,pets eht ekat ot ydaer ,loof eht m'I
.ohce I ",stun s'ehs ,haeY"
,ylitsah dda I ",gnihtyna
”looF ehT“:yojne esaelP
.elbat eht revo gnimool raguoc
.sgniht no krow ot uoy ot og ot em dlot ehs ,haeY"
serutaef s'god eht ni ynygordna gniees
era sdnaW" .stnemevom reh htiw gnibbob
",gnihton eb dluoc tI"
erutcip a ot pu dda tey dna ,gnihton naem llits yam
.daeh ym ekahs dna nworf I   "?tesnus ro nwaD"
.tnemom a rof etatiseh dna don I
,os od ot ton em gnigru gnihtyreve etipseD
.gnitirw lufthguoht fo rehsilbup tnednepedni na
".txen od dluohs I kniht uoy tahw wonk ot tnaw I .haeY"
- er'uoy tub ,od uoy spahrep rO .ton spahreP"
,flesym hctac I "--s'eH
,namsrao eht fo elop eht
...a s'tI .thgirlA"
.elbat eht no tfel
.sgninaem nwod-edispU
"?od I od tahw tub ,hguone riaF"
".noitcaerrevo na ekiL
t'nod--"   .trohs reh gnittuc
,denodnaba snoitaerc eb dluoc tI
,sgniht lla fo gninnigeb eht er'yehT
ta feihc-ni-rotide si ehS
.loohcs ecnis evaH
.kni.oykam no
?uoy ta tuo spmuj tahw ,sdrac eht ta kool uoy nehW ?ees uoy od tahW"
,niaga setats ehs
.pets tsrif eht fo trap s'taht ebyaM .dluohs I tub
".gnihtemos drawot rO"
,egdelwonk si erehT
".stcaf eugav denoitnem ,uoy ot klat ot em dlot ehS
.drac dnoces eht drawot daeh ym don ,krims I   "--ebyaM
.sdrac eerht era ereH" .ecalp fo tuo
.gnitcelfed ,ksa I "?sdrac eerht yhW"
"--tog I ,senutrof gnitcepxe saw I
".ti tel uoy fi gnihtemos naem nac meht otni daer uoy tahW
".noitca fo roloc eht ,wolley dnA
"--re ,m'I taht tsuj swonk ehS" .daeh ym ekahs I
,gnidnatsrednu ot nrut snoitseuQ
.won ma I ohw naht
"?ygrene noitavitca eht evah t'ndid taht em tsap taht erom s'ti oS" ,gnirumrum
:elzzum eninac nael eht ta gnirats ,etatiseh I ".wolley
.flesym ot neve suoibud dnuos I .ksa I "?ecitoN"
,]seiceps[]evitcejda[
.eman dna eciov dna ecaf tnereffid
.em llet t'nod ,tiaW" ,tpurretni I tub
,stnaw eno tahw teg oT
.sdnaW fo egaP...hu ,ehT
,gas sredluohs yM
"?naem nwod edispu gnieb ti seod tahw ,oS"
.spahrep ,noitailimuH ?noitartsurF
.teef rieht ta gnicnad gniht tirips elttil a htiw
,seigrene fo egakcolb a tsuj saw ti taht tsrif ta
.emit eht lla ro yawa thgir ti od ot evah t'nod uoy tub
.elkcuhc a steg sihT
:eb dluow noitseuq txen yM"   .daeh ym ekahs I
.sdrac morf ton ,elpoep morf semoc ecivdA"
".'yeht' ot dehctiws neht dna 'eh' dias uoy
"?sdrows yhw oS"   ".ees ot ecin yllaer s'tI .deticxe er'uoY"
,sdrac fo kced nrow a selffuhs ehs ,kaeps I sa dna ,snigeb ehs
em tnereffid a fo
.gniknis t'nsi ,era sdrows eht erehw ,taob eht fo tnorf ehT" .retaw eht...retaw
.lanoitasrevnoc ,level eciov
.yrros m'I ,zeej hO"   .eviF
.ti fo kniht ot emoc ,sroloc fo ecnalab doog a s'erehT"
?ti t'nsi ,gnieerf elttil a s'tI"
,sdrac eht tuo tuhs I
kcoms reh ot kcab retemomreht eht spilc ehS
.eno kcalb reh ni wap nat ym stap
,su stpurretni emihc A
.taht ta ti evael I
,kcab sih ni deirub sdrows net dna
- ti tuoba gniklat trats ot tnemtnioppa na evah I"
.ecaf ruoy no nettirw s'ti ,hguoht ,t'ndah ehs fi nevE
snirg ehS ".gniniart ni enoemos ,nosrep gnuoy a ,seY"
.ekih a rof ydaer ,elbmut dna hguor kool dluow esoht ni desserd lamina rekrad A
.kniht I ,suonygordna rO .suougibma era serugif eht fo tsom
,htaerb pu-tnep fo hsur a ni nigeb I ",ot tnaw t'nod I"
.ylsuoiruc drac eht ta nwod skool namow redlo ehT "?neht ,nwaD"
.laog a drawot gnivirts ;erus ,semitemos ,efirtS
"?pets taht ekaT ?tahw ot...ot
.lla retfa ,elbmag s'loof a si pets tsrif taht gnikat
dna regdab
,taob eht ,sdrows ehT
- siht fo gnikniht deppots ev'I ezilaer I
".yaw ym uoy hsup ot mom ruoy rof tiaw t'noD
.noisses eht fo gninnigeb eht ta naht yleerf erom kaeps I
,won thgir gnikrow t'nera sdrows esehT
.sdrac eht evoba wap a gnivaw
.sgurhs ehS   ".'eh' ehT
,yltsenrae em ta gnikool ,sesuap ehS ".lla
.sdrac elpmis emos dna regdab elpmis a
,peelsa nellaf t'nsah ti erus ekam ot eciwt ro ecno liat ypor gnihsiws
"?yenruoj a no og ot gniog m'I"
.klat ot tnaw tsuj I tub
.nac I tseb sa elims reh nruter I ,dehsabA
.dloh no tup gnieb thguoht fo tnemevom
,enim no dekcol syats ezag reh tub
.em ta gnilims reh dna
.erutuf dna ,tneserp ,tsaP"
.ecnelis elbatrofmoc a retfa
",oot ,wolley s'nwad ehT"
ezag ym htiw elbat eht fo segde eht gnicart flesym dnif I dna
.eunitnoc ,seye reh ni snoitseuq gniees ,dna ,trulb I
"?taht tsap teg ot woh no sthguoht yna evah uoy oD .mhmM"
,riahc reh ni kcab stis dna shgual ehS
.gnikab dna steewS
.gninnigeb ton ,gnivom ton tub
er'yehT .ti ni sdrows xis sah ni er'yeht taob eht tub
,ereht seunitnoc ecnalab eht
- neeuq eht ,gnik eht ,thgink eht ,egap eht
,drawrof snael ehS
,ffilc a fo egde eht drawot gnippets er'yehT"
".snart m'I taht swonk tsuj ehS"
.gnihtemos hguorht gniog fo krow eht tuoba s'ti
,sdrac rehto eht tuo tuhs I
.enil a ni tuo dial ,sdrac eerhT
esnecni fo tnih oN
.ylraed reh evol I
.yats ot tnaw uoy fi owt rof rennid rehtegot llup nac I .hsur on s'erehT
.trohs em pots sdrow reH
,ssalg ot gnignilc llits ragus fo sdaeb ees
.t'nod yeht on ,oN"
".noitisnart gnitrats ebyaM"
- tius sdrows eht ni sdrac eht fo enoN
".tnaw I tahw teg ot yaw ym hsals dna kcah ot tuoba ton m'I ,lleW"
.trats ot diarfa er'uoy sgniht eb dluoc ti ro
".sey ,ti esu ot tnaw t'ndid rO"
ecnetsisni reh dna
.regdab ylrehtom eht
"?ees uoy od tahW .senil dna selgna ,snoitom ,sroloC
"?siht fo yna reh llet uoy diD"
,syas ehs ",sdrows fo net ehT"   "?lleh eht tahW"