kcab deppihw tnanmer ehT
”.su hcaet ot ydaer dlrow eritne na evah ew meht llet ll’I
,sproc hcraeser eht ecneH
,wap eerf eno reh htiw mrif ti dleh dihcrO .ti deknay dna
.egdelwonk rof ytsriht sa tsuj srehto evah ll’I dna ...kcab eb lliw I“
,sedalb sti no cra amsalp s’raeps eht detingi dna
,setirps erom fo nerrab saw aera eht hguohT
.tuoba dnah reh denrut ylwols dna delggig dihcrO
.tnemele ym si sihT“    suileA yb
.reed a spahrep ,etalugnu laref fo tros emos ot gnignoleb sa
.emoh kcab sdliW tiripS eht ekil gnihton saw sihT
,nrettap fo tros a ni gnislup eb thgim yeht fi derednow dihcrO
,seert gnitcennoc
,reh dnuora tserof eht leef dluoc ehS
tnirps a morf gniog
.yrevocsid tsrif sti ecnis sraey fo sderdnuh eht ni neve
.partskcab reh morf dor a dellup dna
,fael dialni-tiucric eht desserac dihcrO sA
.egailof kciht eht tsdima regnad on gnisnes
.elpoep erew yeht wenk ehs tub
.ti ekam dluoc ehS .deddon neht dna
stoor eht rednu detaolf etirps ehT
.yliraew delims ehs
,reh deticxe sdnal wen gnirevocsid fo aedi ehT
.rekaeps s’dapatad eht hguorht meht deyalp ehS
.teef reh ot kcab dereggats dna
.no depmil ehs sa
,suileA yb ”tuocS ehT“
deppans taht seniv erom ssorca dils ehS
,epacsdnal eht ssorca secalp suoirav fo thgis thguac ehS
.yrtiucric eht ot ti tcennoc ot yaw a htiw pu emoc dah renwo sti fi gnirednow
.emit revo deyaced rettam tnalp eht sa neve
ssom dna trid ehT
elkna reh dnuora desolc deppans eniv A
,sburhs wol revo depael yltfed dihcrO
ni emoc ot smaet hcraeser eht fo tser eht rof efas saw ti tnaem
.ti fo lla yortsed ton did
gnitnuah sti yalp ot deunitnoc langis lanigiro eht ,elihw eht llA
.ti morf detaname esion gninord ,egnarts A
reilrae drawot gnivom neeb dah ehs knurt eert eht dehcaorppa ehS
,spets reh gnitnuoc
resolc detfird etirps ehT
.seye nwo reh htiw ecafrus eht yduts ot thgilhsalf sti gnisu elihw
,reh ot kcab welf tI
airohpue fo etats tnatsnoc A .railimaf tey
.enilced laudarg a dnif ot ni dereep dihcrO dna
.stiucric lanretni fo
.esira deen eht dluohs
evom ot delggurts dihcrO
,yromem detimil s’etirps eht ni swodahs erem erew yehT .elpoep dnA
thguoht eht ta pu til seye s’dihcrO
,tey sdliw eht ni nees reven dah ehs meht fo tsom
.fo elbapac neeb reve dah yteicos reh ni enon noisufni fo level a saw siht tub
,dnuora kool rehtona koot ehS ...hguohtlA
dewollaws dihcrO
sreenigne naetnaltA weN
.flesreh dihcrO ekil stuocs dna
.egailof eht hguorht devom erugif a sa
.setirps gniwolg eht gnizingocer ,delims dihcrO
.ni dekcehc ton dah ehs yhw gnirednow ylbaborp erew swerc noitidepxe nwo reh won yb tub
eson reh dellif taht stnecs eht nevE
”?I ma ,won yracs os ton m’I“ .dihcrO dias ”?eeS“
swolg fo seires a gniwollof
,noiger a fo ytefas eht enimreted ot tnatropmi os sa nees tey
.reh ot txen knurt eert eht ot revo decnalg neht
,tnalp suorovinrac ybraen A
.taht no pu dekcip etirps elttil eht taht demees ti gnol erofeb dna
noisuF siht fo ecnedive erom dnif ot
tnalp dnuorg ybraen a ot denrut dihcrO
.sedoc eht tuoba thguat neeb dah ehs tahw rehtegot deceip ehs dna
reh dniheb deyaws srae pol gnol fo riap A
,seye reh gnisolC
.niarret nevenu eht ssorca deeps reh peek ot spoh gnidnuob fo seires a ot
,sdliW tiripS nretsae eht fo snoiger detrahcnu-llits eht nihtiw peeD
.gorf a naht regral erutaerc a emusnoc ot hguone gib gnihtyna reven tub
.wap rehto reh tuo dleh dna
.dlroW dlO eht fo tcudorp tcerid a ,rehtar tub
,dnuorg eht no wap a htiW
.erom ees ot dah ehS
.sdliW tiripS gnignahc-reve eseht tuoba erom nrael dna
elbissop si ecnetsixeoc taht foorp saw ti
depley dihcrO .reh deknay dna
.mlap yzzuf reh fo elddim eht ni delttes dna
.noisuF yb dehcuot neeb sah noiger a taht ecnedivE
.tuo gniog neeb dah langis siht gnol woh gnillet on saw erehT
.dnuorg eht no dednal dna llef sevael nehw gnikaerb retfa detcennocer yeht fi sa saw ti
.erom ecno ecneserp reh gnidnapxe elihw ecnatsid reh tpek dna
niaga senot cidolem ,dehctip eht gnihctac
.flesti ytitne na emaceb dna
.tsap detfird ylizal etirps ynit a
thguoht fo mrof evitimirp a sa debircsed eb tseb dluoc tahw fo tnih tsethgils eht detceted ehs sa delims dihcrO ,did ti sA
elohknis eht fo tuo debmilc dihcrO
detanicsaf ylrettu saw dihcrO
seluspac eht fo emoS
tfahs raeps eht dnuora sregnif reh krow ot deirt tibbar eht
.emoc dluoc maet noitidepxe deppiuqe-ylidaer erom a litnu
,dluoc ehs tseb sa ecnatsid eht degduj ehs ,nwod gnicnalG
sevael fo yponac kciht a hguorht enohs thgilnus tnaidar fo sehctap
.yb dessap ehs sa sevael s’nref a ssorca dnah a dehsurb dihcrO ,erutats trohs
,etirps eht ot pu decnalg ehS
dapatad reh tuo dleh ehS
”.siht evivrus lliw I
.stros fo ,drocer a saw tI
emit emas eht ta tub
,kcab reh dellup yletaidemmi tI
.reh dnuora dedaf yllaudarg swolg eht sa
.tuo meht gnidnes saw gnihtemos ekil
,gnikaeps llits dna
.swolg tiucric eht dnoyeb ssenthgirb tniaf a gniees
.tserup sti ta erutan sa dematnu sa saw ecalp sihT
.ruf reh morf retaw eht ekahs ylsuorogiv ot gnisuap ,tuo debmilc dna
,sniur sti ni tneserp llits tey msylcatac a ni deyortsed ecno dlrow a
.tcerroc sgnidaer eht evorp ot hguone raelc saw dna
,gniklaw deunitnoc ehs sa nwod gnicnalG
.roolf tserof tnarbiv a etanimulli ot
,dne tnulb eht htiw nwod debbaj dna reh dniheb tuo raeps hcet reh dleh ehs erofeb
.dnuorg eht otni sedalb eht debbaj dna
langis elbidua na dewohs sgnidaer ehT
.langis eht fo ecruos eht saw hcihw
,noitingocer dnoyeb raf saw tI
seye reh denepo tibbar ehT
.ti ni deppart yerp eht dna revaew sti htiw gnola
.emoh kcab yaw ehT
,yfitnedi etiuq ton dluoc ehs yaw eltbus emos ni
egnarts a saw ereht tub
.eye s’dnim reh ni tuo ekam dluoc ehs sepahs eht ni
.gnimoclewnu raeppa ton did ti
.erutaerc elttil eht morf
,nopaew a dna kcits gniklaw a htob sa elbatius
dehcaorppa dihcrO .seniv dna doow eht fo ecafrus eht raen neve
noiger siht gnitalupop erew setirps eht tcaf ehT
.citats eht tsdima
”,emoceb evah uoy tahw wonk I dna ,ereh llits m’I“
dellac eb ot saw ti gnivlovni hcraeser eht dna
,wonk ot detnaw ehs erom hcum os saw erehT
,srepsihw fo tsetniaf eht htiW
.sterces sti gnikcolnu fo epoh eht ni
.dnuorg eht ot swap reh tup dna
.reh dnuora detaolf setirps gniwolg erom sa no gniunitnoc
ssam eht gninnacs ylsuoenatlumis ,dapatad reh tuo dleh dna
rennacs eht morf stuodaer eht ot dehctiws neht ehS
,msylcatac eht erofeb dlroW dlO eht fo tnanmer a ro noitazilivic tnatsid rehtona erew eseht rehtehW
:saw ylurt ti deveileb yeht tahw ti dellac llits srehcraeser dleif wollef reh dna dihcrO hguoht ”,ecneicsrepyh“
htap reh ni eniv part yreve decils dna
!otni nrob saw ehs tnemele eht saw sihT .tuocs a saw ehS
.erom ecno ecneserp reh htiw tuo gnihcaer
.wenk yeht ylno egaugnal a ni daer eb ot sdrocer eseht dewolla taht
.no deunitnoc dihcrO ,os nevE
.sesnes denutta reh htiw neve
tfihs yllaudarg ot demees tserof gninekrad eht
,daeha devohs dna
deid dna detliw stnalp sa dniheb tfel yrtiucric fo stnemgarf—
,sdliw eseht ni neddih saw rewsna eht wenk ehS
,serutaerc elttil suoiruc hcuS
slavretni ta yalp ot deunitnoc senot eht sa
kcas noitsegni sti pu edam dah taht senarbmem eht gnilrufnu
tcesni lanoisacco na ro srewolf morf
no dehsalf neercs ehT
,stserof eht ni emitefil reh ni stnalp suorovinrac fo ytnelp nees dah ehS
.dlroW dlO eht deyortsed taht msylcatac eht desuac ev’thgim tahw osla tub
,retlah reh ssorca dna redluohs eno revo depparw neeb dah hsas nayc-dna-eulb krad evitcnitsid a hguoht
,gnihtaerb reh deidaets dna deleenk dihcrO
.meht gnisnes fo elbapac esoht ot saedi elpmis htiw gnitcaretni fo elbapac
niaga egrahc amsalp s’raeps reh detingi dihcrO
,tnew ti kcab raf woh erus ton saw ehS
.doots ehs erehw thgir meht fo sreyal dna sreyal eb dluoc erehT
?meht dnuora dlrow eht ,yletamitni
devom ylneddus meht fo enO
.laer saw ecneserp sti tub
,kool resolc a teg ot deirt dihcrO sA
.yna nopu elbmuts ot hguone ykcul eb tuocs a dluohs
.epols peets evissam a nwod
krab eht ni skcarc eht rednu swolg tniaf deciton ehS
.enihcam evissam a fo edisni eht rO
,eciwt dehsilbup neeb osla sah eH
,denot fo eod tibbar A
nees reven dah ehS
.yb rednaw ot erutaerc gnitcepsusnu txen eht ni llup ot ydaer
meht gnoma degnoleb ehs wenk dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.erew yeht thguoht ydobyreve thgil fo sbro gnitaolf ,suoiruc eht tsuj ton erew setirps eseht taht gnitbuod on saw ereht tub ,llet ton dluoc ehs
,reh dniheb tserof gnivil eht ta kcab ecnalg a htiW
.gnippop senob tlef ehS
,thgieh nwo reh naht rellat tsuj htgnel a ot dednetxe tI
yawa selim dnasuoht a dnalsi natiloportem gnilwarps a no devil won ehs tcaf eht dna
.morf gnimoc saw langis eht erehw saw siht
,sitnaltA weN ni desu esoht ekilnu ton selciheV
.kcab denrut neht
epols eht rof dedaeh ehS
nirg tub pleh t’ndluoc ehS
,stserof eht ni pu gniworg retfA
swolg was neve ehs ,pu gnicnalG
.erom gnidiova fo sepoh ni
.uoy morf raeh ot evol
.edis rehto eht no knab eht ta srekcilf erom gniciton
.ssorca reh pleh ot seniv ro seert nellaf on was tub
,etelpmoc gninnacS
.egailof eht ni tneserp yrtiucric euqinu eht morf gnitaname
,stoor eht ni deddebme stiucric fo eldnub esned a ot sedalb eht gnihcuoT
”tuocS ehT“ saw sihT
,etamitigel dnuos ot denimreted
.wenk dihcrO dlrow ehT
,detfihs ylizal tnalp ehT
noisuF ygolonhcet-erutan fo tros siht fo seicacirtni eht taht
.rewolf ekil-eluspac nepo eguh a drawot dellup gnieb ,drah dnuorg eht tih dna
setirps fo ecneserp ehT
.tnemnorivne navlys eht rof evol reh denessel reven
.reh dnuora lla neerg hsul fo yrenecs eht ni koot
.deleenk dna dehcaorppa ylluferac ehS
.gniugirtni tey ,eireE
.yrellag sih ni krowtra dna seirots htob gniwohs
,dapatad reh gniretsloh
.erom ecno ecneserp reh htiw tuo gnihcaer
dehcaorppa ylsuoituac ehs ,tuo raepS
.emit hguorht derehtaew ,sgnidliuB
”.gnihtyreve wonk ot tnaw I“ .duola dias ehs
,sedaced morf doow nworgrevo dna seniv fo ssam a raen gnirevoh etirps eht gnidnif ,ni dils dna
.ffo rehtraf snref fo gnipuorg a drawot niaga ffo detrad etirps ehT
.rewol slevel wef tsuj
edis rehto eht no ecafrus eht ekorb ehS
,stnalpmi cinoib detcefrep ecnis gnol dah sreenigne naetnaltA weN
.oga seirutnec sseltnuoc devil taht yteicos tneicna siht dniheb raf llits saw
,htgnel toof-eerht lluf sti ot ti dednetxe
.rewolf der thgirb
.otni flesreh nettog dah ehs tahw tsuj ezilaer ot nageb ehs
,dnuorg eht ni spid dna ,seniv dehcterts
.derettum dihcrO ”...ti did yehT“
.esab eht dehcaer ehs litnu
dnuora dekool dihcrO ?llac ssertsid taht ni detluser revetahw
”.metsysoce eritne na esuF ot woh tuo derugif yllautca yehT“
,emac ehs yaw eht drawot kcab denrut dna doots dihcrO
,htworgrednu gninekciht-yllaudarg hguorht gniklaw teiuq fo setunim retfA
,deleenk dna knabrevir eht dehcaorppa dihcrO
.dnuorg yssom eht gnola deklaw ehs sa skcart yna tfel yldrah swaptoof daorb reh dna
.dnim ton did ehs tub ,ruf etihw reh deillus dah
meht yrd ot srae pol reh gnihsurb ,no deklaw ehS
,ngierof dna detsiwT .tnetnoc tey
.rotces siht ni dnuof neeb yllanif ev’yehT
epahs ekil-yek a otni sedalb eerht sti detfihs pit ekil-raeps latem denettalf a ,dne sti tA
,reh tuoba decnalg dna
,ffilc daorb a erofeb tlah a ot deddiks ehS
sdliw eht ni gnitsixe llits noisuF fo ecnedive eht tey
evoba denekciht yponac eht sa resraps gnimoceb erew hcihw
.ria eht deffins ehs sa niaga dehctiwt sreksihw s’dihcrO
,no rehtruf gnitiaw eb thgim tahw ta derednop dna
denediw seye reH
thgil tniaf fo sehsalf tnatsid was ylraelc dihcrO tub
,edisa tserof eht fo evoL
.sdop eht dnuora dna ni ssenitpme
.raw-fo-gut a ni reh dellup stnalp rehto owt eht sa niap ni gnicniw
.esaenu lufthgirf dna
reh gnidnuorrus erutan war fo ecneserp eht gniyojne
”.em swonk ti sa llew sa ecalp siht wonk I
,efil ot deralf senil tiucriC
.ni pu nworg dah ehs dlroW weN eht fo sdliw eht nihtiw neddih
dapatad eht no gnimit eht detsujda dna
detsixe llits swerc noitidepxe rehto eht
,drawtuo daerps swolg ehT
,emac ehs yaw eht denruter dihcrO
”tuocS ehT“   :yojne esaelP
,nwo sti fo ecneserp a ffo gnivig gniht gnivil yreve
senil yrevlis elbakatsimnu eht deciton ehs
.raeps reh htiw tuoba deppihw dna reh dniheb dnuos a draeh ehS ?thgiR
,no rehtruf denekciht yponac ehT
.sega sseltnuoc rof denodnaba neeb gnivah
,wohemos taht deciton dna
roloc fo hsalf A
,eerf sthguoht nwo reh tel dihcrO
.yduts ot smaet hcraeser eht rof ciler wen a nopu delbmuts evah thgim ehs
,dapatad reh pu dleh ehS
erew seigolonhcet tneicna sa devivrus tsap eht fo seiromem ecracS
reh dniheb polf srae pol reh ekam ot hguone tsaf
,daeha tserof esned eht fo tser eht ot
.elohknis a revo dehcterts stoor s’eert eht erehw ot nwod detaolf ti
.debrutsid gnieb tuohtiw snosaes sseltnuoc hguorht
.erolpxe ot ”desoppus“ saw ehs raf woh sseldrager
.srepeek-drocer erew yehT
,ti nihtiw setirps eht gnidulcni
,setanidrooc reh deggol dna dapatad eht derewol ehs
.dlroW weN eht dliub ot denifer dna
noitazilivic decnavda reh tcaf eht ta
.tserof eht nihtiw repeed
,reh dnuora lla detfird setirps eht sA
.erom devol tuocs a gnihton saw erehT
,noitarolpxe rof efas si noiger a etacidni ton yam ro yam taht anemonehp modnar tsuj toN
.meht htiw tcaretni dluoc ehs sa hcus stuocs detfig ylno dna
,doots tibbar ehT
.revo dettort dna
ecnaraeppa eht ffo evig dna
.deraeppasid snoitidepxe lanigiro eht ecnis gniyalp neeb dah langis ehT
gniugirtni erom eht lla
,dnim denutta reh htiw ,dihcrO
,won ees dluoc ehs lla erew reh dnuora srekcilf ehT
.meht edisni swodahs tuo ekam ylerab dluoc ehS
seye reh desolc neht ehS
flesreh dednimer dihcrO tey
tserof eht fo efil tnarbiv eht ,reh dnuora llA
lley deniap a tuo tel ehS
sreksihw dna ruf reh htiw tlef ehs tahw morf sucof reh detfihs ehs ,dnim reh htiw tuo gnihcaeR
,edis rehto eht no gnitiaw etirps eht ta dekool neht ehS
ecnaraeppa s’tnalp egnarts eht fo eton koot ehs sa deyalps srae s’dihcrO
.llet ot dehsiw ti seirots eht esnes dluoc
ppa noitagivan s’dapatad reh detavitca ehS
.stnemnorivne suordnow gnirevocsid dna
.tuoba gnitfird setirps fo puorg rehtona ni devreserp yromem a sa
daeha edorts dna
.rehtruf erolpxe ot reh deripsni ylniatrec tub
.nalc reh fo snrettap gniwolf eht gniyalpsid
tiaw ot evah dluow ytisoiruc reH
.noitazilivic ees tsael ta dluoc ehs wenk ehs tub
dna stcA namuhnI ni
,dlroW dlO eht morf srossecederp reh yb deticer yllaunitnoc
,deklaw ehs sa niaga langis eht deyalp dna
.rebmuls fo snoe retfa nekawaer ot gnilggurts tsap a fo stnanmeR
.etal oot dnoces tilps a tsuj tnecs teews railimaf taht thguac tub
.erom yna deciton neve ylerab dna ti ot desu llew saw ehs
”?wollof ot em tnaw uoY“
,nekorb fo seires lanoisacco na thguac srae evitisnes reh tub
.sdneirf reh htiw ti erahs ot ecnahc eht dna
.noitazilivic yb debrutsidnu gnieb fo htrow ’seirutnec ylbaborp
,dlroW dlO eht fo stnanmeR
.tnemnorivne siht ni ecalp reh wenk llits ehs
.htiw railimaf saw ehs enon ekil erew
,yawa dekcab tibbar ehT
.aera noitidepxe eht fo egde eht ta kcab dnif ot reh rof
.tnemnorivne eht hpargotohp ot pu ti gnidloh
dlroW dlO morf devivrus euqinhcet fo tros emos neeb evah osla thgim
,pu kcab dereggats dna tsirw reh dnuora seniv eht ffo dewang dihcrO ,gnitnaP
.drocer ot hcum oot saw erehT
nwod dedacsac thgilnus fo snobbiR
pots a ot dellor dihcrO .mutnemom reh htiw dnuorg yssom eht ssorca drawrof delbmut dna delruc ,gnidnal nopu
dapatad reh ot tnes sgnidaer ehT
.seiromem derettacs fo wolf a tlef dihcrO dna
.dnim s’dihcrO otni derekcilf
.esolc detfird eno dna
.sffilc eht neewteb dewolf revir a ,woleb rehtruF
.ti etarapes ot eniv eht no nwod debbats dna
,epacsdnal eht detaroced
,dewolf senil yrtiucric eht yaw ehT
,dapatad reh dewots dna
,sniev dna sllec sti nihtiw elbisiv yleraB
sehsalf ynit dna
.sknurt eert dna seniv eht tuohguorht senot cidolem
msylcatac eht retfa dniheb tfel
.noiger siht ni hcraes ot deraelc erew stuocs erehw fo segde eht dnoyeb raf enog dah ehs taht was dna
pitregnif a no detser tI
.srats ynit fo dleif a hguorht gniklaw erew ehs fi sa
,bew redips a pu gnithgil
eniv part driht a dereggirt ti erehw ,dnuorg eht tih raeps reh tel dna
,ylenol dna detalosI
.tuoba detfird swolg ynit elihw lla
,sdliw eht ni desiar saw ehS
.erofeb esned os yrtiucric desuF
.tsirw reh dnuora depsalc eno dna
,dexim sdnuos eht sA
pag eht ssorca reh dehcnual sgel tibbar lufrewop reH
,tneitnes ylerab tsuj eb ot deveileb erew setirpS
,erutan ot ”klat“ dna ecneserp rieht dnapxe ot stuocs rof ytiliba euqinu eht taht
.daeha tserof gnirekcilf eht fo tser eht morf reh etarapes ot
.niaga dehctiwt sreksihw reH
.tenalPruF yb 8 RAOR
werc roirp eht did rO
.ton dah snoitidepxe suoiverp eht lliks a dessessop ehs derebmemer ehs nehT
reh derussa srae evitisnes reH
.pecib reh no retsloh sti morf dapatad reh devomer dna
.meht fo yna ezingocer ton did ehs tub
dnuora dekool dihcrO
stiucric eht hguorht langis sti tsacdaorb ot ti wolla tbuod on dluow sihT
.ynomrah niatniam ot redro ni devresed stnemele eseht tcepser eht fo
,ecaf reh no deraeppa nirg dewa na sA
.no deunitnoc dna swaptoof erab reh morf trid eht dekcik ehS
meht dezingocer dihcrO
.tnemele ym si sihT“
.ecneserp nevig xodarap A
,deugirtni ,desuap ehS
.knurt eert kciht a ot txen revoh ot
egaugnal tneicna na ni ekops
slavretni tes ta ni demihc yehT
,dehcraeser ,derevocsider
.gnihtaerb reh dellits dna
,erolpxe ot degnol traeh reH
.devirra setirps eht erofeb oga gnol os deraeppasid snoitidepxe suoiverp redlo eht fo emos yhw ot
aedi eht derednop dihcrO
.tserof eht fo nrob eno sa
,erehwemos nward gnieb ylevitca saw ehs taht ytilibissop eht derednop ehs emit siht hguoht
,dnuorg yssom eht ssorca nwod diks flesreh tel dna
,flesti erutan ni desiar neeb dah ehS
.flesti tserof eht ton fi ralucitrap ni eno on ot
,egral a raen revoh ot yawa detrad neht
eulc a evah won yam ehs taht noitazilaer eht ta
.deredduhs ,nepo eno siht
,etirps eht dennacs dna niaga dapatad reh tuo koot ehS
”?eno elttil ,morf emoc uoy od erehW“
,stcafitra dlroW dlO erar gniyduts sraey tneps dah
.citats esiwrehto saw tahw ni deirub
.esolc fael daorb a dleh dna
daehraeps eht dnuora deppans taht
.swaptoof reh htaeneb yrtiucric erom fo ecneserp eht tlef dna
,htaerb rof gnipsaG
.sknurt eert eht fo emos pu yawtrap dna roolf tserof eht dnuora gnikans seniv desuF erom gnola
.erofeb secnatsni ynam os ekil
etirps eht dewollof ehS
,erutan desuF fo esnapxe esned siht ni erehwemos fi derednow ehS
.sevren ekil dekool yeht esned os erew senil ehT
,rotacinummoc deddebme eht fo otohp kciuq a koot ehS
.esoprup a dah yeht suoivbo saw ti
.dnuorg eht gnirevoc rettam tnalp citoxe fo sessam eht no pets yreve htiw swaptoof reh rednu pu gnithgil ylmid swolg tniaf deciton ehs
gnignir cidolem a otni gnidnelb erofeb gnilbraw ddo na otni denibmoc yeht
lios eht ni tneserp ssamoib eht ni setacilis enillatsyrc ,deifirup fo ecnedive tniaf dekcart ehs ,dapatad reh nO
.dedrocer neeb dah yrotsih sti sa gnol sa rof
,retirw a er’uoy fi dnA
.flesreh ot dias ehs ”,skeew eerht ni gnithgis etirps tsriF“
.ybraen fael rehtona no gnilttes ti was dna yawa dettilf dah taht
…efas saw retaw eht detacidni
noitazilivic dlroW weN fo ssergorp eht deripsni dah
reh ni gnihcaorppa edis rehto ehT
.selppad ni derevoc sebolg nellows eb ot deraeppa tahw dessap dihcrO ,deklaw ehs sA
.nrael ot erom hcum os sah llits ehs devorp tserof elohw siht tey
,meht ediug pleh ot noitamrofni hguone naht erom kcab gnirb dluow ehs
yrevocsid fo llirht eht rof erom ecno deticxe
?dlroW dlO eht morf yeht ereW
.rethgit dellup seniv eht sa
,erofeb neeb dah ti sa deniamer aera eritne ehT
,leef dna ecneserp nwo rieht htiw tuo hcaer ot ytiliba rieht nialpxe yeht dluoc esle woH .cigaM tiripS
.retaw eht otni flesreh dehcnual dna dehcuorc ehS
,deklaw ehs sa flesreh ot demmuh yltfos ehS
”.deirrow teg ot gnitrats saw I“
tnecsed reh gniwols
.tnaem senot eht tahw derednop ehs sa dehctiwt sreksihw s’dihcrO
,wodahs ni tserof eht fo tser eht gniduorhs
.ria eht hguorht deraos ehs dna
dlroW dlO eht deyortsed taht msylcatac eht taht
?spahrep ,rewop ward ot yaw A
,revewoh ,cinori ti dnuof ehS
.gol noitidepxe s’yad eht rof yrtne txen reh deraperp ehs sa sedom gninnacs tnereffid hguorht dehctiws neercs ehT
,riah nwo reh erew yeht fi sa
.erehwyreve saw tI
.ereht yletinifed saw gnihtemos wenk ehs
,evitca tsuj ton erew stiucric eht
,deugirtni ylneddus
,sllec lamred s’rettam eht htaenrednu tsuj
.sregnif reh gnoma dna ssorca decnad ti
.tserof repeed eht fo sthgis eht ni koot ehs sa
.raen reh werd daeha pu hsalf A
.oga gnol os ereh no tnew tahw gnirednow
srae evitisnes reH
.emils ni derevoc senob fo ssam a tuo gnillips
.sdnaldoow eht otni repeed tnew ti sa etirps eht htiw pu gnipeek
deleenk ehS .aera noitidepxe eht fo egde eht dnoyeb enog dah ehs raf woh tsuj dezilaer ylneddus neht ehS
saw yrtiucric desuF
,mra reh gnibbarg eniv eht dehsals dna dnuora raeps reh deppihw dihcrO .ti gnieerf dna eniv eht gnicils
.edoc enot fo mrof evitimirp a dezingocer yletaidemmi dihcrO
.no rehtruf dnuos rehtona thguac
,tneserp llits hcet desuF fo stnanmer eht htiw nevE
,thgilnus fo snmuloc ssorca dehsalf tibbar ehT
,tnenitnoc eht gnittod setats-ytic suoirav eht gnomA
,rekcilf hcae htiw drawtuo gnidaerps erew swolg eht fi sa demees ti dna
.yawa gnitfird ylizal ydaerla saw ti tub
,tsael yrev eht tA
meop sseldne na saw tI
,dliw eht ni dnuof ygolonhcet tsol htiw tcaretni ot yllacificeps dengised saw taht
.noitazilivic yb dehcuotnu tserof a fo elddim eht ni eb dluow revir lacipyt a tahw taht elirets erom dna
,elim a revo llew ekil tlef tahw retfA
sehctiws sti fo eno tih ot
,rekaeps s’dapatad reh morf taeper ot deunitnoc langis nekorb eht sA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
knurt eert daorb a ot txen deleenk tibbar ehT
,sproc hcraeser ehT
.ecnereffidni htiw kcab derewsna ylno tserof ehT
,ecneserp reh hguorht tub
,raeps hcet reh tuo dellup ehS
.tupni fo hsur eht tsdima nezorf evah ot demees ti tub
.ecneserp yrev reh sa wenk ylno ehs tahw htiw tuo dehcaer dihcrO ,reh htaeneb yrtiucric desuF fo wolf eht gnisnes ylerab tsuj
,yalpsid sti nwod gnillorcs eb ot atad fo sbog gnitcepxe
.ecnalab eligarf siht ni
.koobgol reh rof gnidaer rehtona gnitteg
,emoclewnu saw eno on ,ereh tuO
.wodahs ni rekrad emaceb aera eht dna
senil yrtiucric eht pu til swolg ehT
.meht dnuora dlrow eht ot ”klat“
dedaf elims reh dna
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,suileA yb
.troppus rof raeps eht gnisu
tnecs teews euqinu dna
.are eht fo seirevocsid gniticxe tsom eht fo eno neeb dah ygolonhcet dna erutan fo noisuF ehT
;reh ot hcum derettam ti taht toN
.ecalp eno ni gniyats fo thguoht eht raeb yldrah dluoc ehs ,niaga nehT
,detcepxe sa ,looc tlef tI
,noisiv reh ni evom ot demees gnihtoN
,nrettap a ni gnislup deedni erew swolg eht ees dluoc ehs ,ereH
.tuocs a sa efil reh tuohguorht draeh dah ehs
,derettum ehs ”...tuocs a ma I“
.noituac nwo reh fo etips ni
ssorca dehcterts revir dicalp a ,no rehtruF
.esiw eb ton dluow regnol yna
.doohtik reh fo seiromem mraw gnillitsni dna
dnuos eht dehctam ti dezilaer dihcrO
,ereh neeb dah ti gnol woh tsuj ta gnitnih
.knab rewol a ot nwod dna ssorca gnittilf etirps eht gniees
.sitnaltA weN ni kcab slicnuoc hcraeser suoititsrepusnu yllamron eht ot neve
.epacsdnal eht ssorca gnidnetxe stiucric desuF eht hguorht osla tub
!rof devil ehs yrevocsid fo tros eht saw siht
,yerp roirp morf nellows ydaerla erew
.ngised ni ngierof tey
wap a detfil ylsuoituac dihcrO
.sksir eht rettam on noiger siht tuoba erom nrael ot regae ,dewollof dna
ti ot did noisuF revetahw dnoyeb nworg dah tI
.dluow tuocs elbaiv yna sa
.tenalp tnereffid yleritne na morf fi sa
yretsym a deniamer
deslup ,oot ,ti sa elbaeciton erom hcum
yromem fo secart derettacS
pu nepo ot meht gnisrever dna
.yawa dettilf ti tub ,pu dehcaer ylluferac dihcrO
sregnad euqinu rieht gnidlareh emit emas eht ta elihw
,dapatad reh deretsloh dna doots dihcrO
aera noitidepxe devorppa eht fo egde eht no ydaerla saw ehs tcaf eht derongi yletarebiled dihcrO
,bro gniwolg a naht erom gnihton ekil dekool llits ti
hctiws a dehcaer bmuht reH
ytisoiruc fo tuo snoiger wen nopu gnilbmuts naht rehtar
enola ereh tuo gnieb taht hguone foorp saw reh dnuora lla tlef ehs ecneserp gnimlehwrevo ,egnarts ehT
.yaw tahw ni tuo ekam etiuq ton dluoc ehs hguoht
.emac ehs yaw eht kcab gninrut
,ytisoiruc ni ti denimaxe dihcrO
,ekops dna srehto ynam os fo ecneserp eht gnoma
gel reh debbur dihcrO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,dekrow noisuF ygolonhcet/erutan woh fo gnidnatsrednu reraelc a tnarg ylno ton dluoc taht
.elkna reh ta eniv tsal eht htiw kcab gnidils reh gnidnes
.sesnes nwo reh dnoyeb leef ot ecneserp reh htiw tuo dehcterts ehs
.noisuF fo sngis nedal-tiucric gniraeb sknurt eert dna sevael erom gniciton
,pu esolc siht nevE
rewop fo epyt siht taht detsisni
.deeps pu dekcip dna dennirg ehS
meht tsniaga dehsurb ehs sa
,reh dnuora saw tserof eht krad woh tsuj gnieeS
,ecneserp s’tibbar eht nI
dnuora raeps reh deppihw dihcrO
.swolg tniaf htiw
,parts sti no kcab ti dewots dna raeps reh detcarter dihcrO ...suoiruC
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tceted dluoc srae tibbar evitisnes reh ylno taht
tsulrednaw reh yfsitas ot tfig rehtona saw dnal eht tuocs ot ytinutroppo yreve dna
?elbissop neve taht sI
reh fo tnorf ni etirps elttil eht dnuof ehs
.nar ehs elihw cnys slangis owt eht tel dna
d’I dna ,margeleT dna rettiwT no yggodikahk@ m’I ,wohs eht rof tif doog a eb thgim taht yrots trohs a evah uoy dna
rekaeps delffum sti hguorht tsuj ton
,langis ssertsid eht deyalp llits ti wohemos tub
.skcor degrembus eht tsdima deslup swolg
.tcelgen fo seirutnec retfa neve decnavda erom raf deniamer
,esle ydobyna naht rehtruf rednaw ot ycnednet reh ot desu gnol erew smaet hcraeser eht
shtap wen gnirolpxe
,yponac kciht eht fo edahs eht nI
rednow ni delims tibbar ehT
,wollof ot deunitnoc ehs dna yawa detfird etirps ehT
,no deunitnoc etirps ehT
.nihtiw morf ylmid gniwolg
...desuF“ .senil yrtiucriC
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.retaw eht otni sedalb s’raeps hcet reh gnippid
,dehcaorppa dihcrO sA
.derettum ehs ”?efildliw
.raeps eht htiw decnys ti sa dapatad reh dekcehc dihcrO
,emanresu emas eht rednu ytiniffAruF ta dnuof eb nac ohw
,sdliw eht ni pu gniworg fo seiromem nwo reh htiw etirps eht ot ”kaeps“ ecneserp reh gnittel
ecnedive detsixe llits ereht erehw
.maws ehs sa tuo ekam dluoc ehs enon saw ti tub
,dnuora lla deohce gnizzub dna ,skwauqs ,sprihc tnatsiD
,mottob eht morf denepo dna
stoor eht rednu dekcud tibbar ehT
,hctip ni enotonom ylriaf demees tI
,rehtruf drawpu dettilf etirps ehT
.erolpxe ot ecnahc eht ta deticxe
.ssenkrad s’tserof eht ot detsujda seye reh sa dnuos eht dewollof ylluferac dihcrO
eert evissam eht dnoyeb dekool dna
?epacsdnal eht hguorht gnisruoc
.rewolf ylio ,suomrone na fo
ecafrus yssalg eht htaeneb dedilg ylhtooms tibbar ehT
sknurt eert eht gnola srewolf eluspac fo rebmun a dna dnuorg eht tuoba nwerts seniv part erom gniciton
.os ro sdnoces evif yreve senot emas eht—
.raen saw gib gnihtemoS .ezorf ehS
.eert eht fo noitrop a pu gnidnetxe seniv wolley dnif ot dnuora dekool dna
noitcerid egnahc etirps eht was dihcrO
,nemo doog a ekil saw
.noiger siht ni detseretni saw ytisrevinu eht rednow oN .dennirg ehS
,retsaf nar tibbar eht sa rehtruf reh gniddib
,emoh kcab stserof eht naht tnereffid yletinifed saw sihT
.ti morf tuo gnignis senot cidolem
.retaw eht otni wap a dils neht
.nihtiw saw tahw ot
.tuoba gnirettiks stsaeb laref ynit neve dna ,sburhs eritne ,sevael
.depael dna drawrof detnirps neht
,tnedive saw epacsdnal eht hguorht gniwolf rewop ehT
,laminim erew stnemrag reH
.rewolf eht tsniaga deppals dna
,eunitnoc ot hguone efas tlef llits ehs
,pets reh ni gnirps a htiw no deunitnoc dihcrO
”.sega rof denodnaba gnieb retfa flesti desuF metsysoce eht rO“ ,dedda ehs
.llac ssertsid a saw tI
,yletelpmoc ti depolevne ylraen dah krab eert ehT
,ecneserp reh hguorhT
.knurt eert ybraen a morf tuo gnikcits gnihtemos deciton ehS
snoitseuq htiw decar dnim reH
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,daeha dettort ehS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,no eunitnoc ot reh dellepmoc tI
.aera eht yevrus dna
.mlap reh evoba gnirevoh ,pu detaolf tI
,dna flesreh deidaer dihcrO ,thgis
....won yb enog eb dluow meht denetaerht revetahw yleruS
,drawno deunitnoc dna denrut ylluferac ehS
ecap reh dewols ehS
,ecnaraeppa gnidoberof ylgnimees sti fo etips ni tey
ssenredliw gnitfihs-reve eht otni tuo og ot stroffe etanidrooc ot tsrif eht saw
flesti sitnaltA weN
.reh dnuora lla drawtuo gnihcnarb
.kcab teg ot dedeen dna ,won hguone raf enog yletinifed dah ehS .deknilb dihcrO
nwod decnalg ehS
.mitciv s’tnalp eht fo senob derevoc-emils eht no snrettap egnarts deciton ehs nehT
...desuac tahw eb ytiliba siht fo kcal ’snoitidepxe roirp eht dluoC
.tuoba delcric dna rewolf eht ot denruter neht dna
.gnitsacdaorb erew yeht
eman reh deripsni taht seye ogidni thgirb ,pu gnicnalG
.ti otni pat ot elba wef detfig eht gnoma saw ehs dna
dluoc taht tsrif eht saw noitareneg reH
.gnol rof terces elttil nwo reh eb regnol on dluow esidarap fo ecils rehtona taht gniwonk ,dehgis dihcrO ,noitazilaer taht htiW
atad fo mrof a sa tsixe won
,elbisneherpmoc neve ylerab ,yzah erew yehT
knil wen laitnetop A
.stnalp suorovinrac eht fo owt neewteb reh gnihcterts dna rehto eht gnitlah
.swaptoof reh rednu thgiew reh fo erusserp eht morf pu gnithgil wolg tniaf eht ta nwod neht
.reh ot revo detaolf dna nihtiw morf degreme setirps fo retsulc llams A
,ti ni deddebme ecived rotacinummoc are-dlo na dnuof dna
.nosaer a rof siht ekil depahs saw tI
,maws ehs sa reh woleb nevE
ruf etihw ssorca decnad dna
tneserp llits yrtiucric desuF morf thgil fo srekcilf ynit deniamer ereht ,wohemos teY
,rennacs sti detavitca ehs dna
,niaga tfihs ot demees reh dnuora tserof eht ,ylnedduS
,dias ehs ”,nrael ot tnaw I erom hcum os s’erehT“