.oihO .revo skcolb owT .niaM no ton sÕtI
Ó,tol a sseug erus uoYÒ Ó.sseug I ,haey É hu
.detniop ehS ÓÑereht nwod dekrap I
,trihs-t a dna snaej
Ó?azzip rof gniog mÕI kniht uoy od yhWÒ
.htaerb deretsulf ,peed a gnikat ,liat ypor ,elisneherp sih htiw kcurt sih ta detniop eH
Ó.emoh gnitteg eb dluohs I
.tnorferots eht ot kcab trac gnippohs sih leehw ot gninrut
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.railimaf yleugav dekool ehS
.nottub pot eht gnissim saw ,dialp dna lennalf ,trihs-t eveels-trohs A
.decnuob ydob reh yaw eht deciton nosremE ,ecnatsid siht morf nevE
Ó?deifitrec uoy erAÒ Ó.uoy hcaet nac IÒ
Ó.hguone drah gniyrt ton erÕuoy ebyaM ?erus uoYÒ
.dda ot gnihtyna evah tÕndid nosremE
,drawrof gnicaf elab eno :elpmis saw siH
,eritta lausu sih nI
.spot ,setunim neetfiF
Ó.seirolac ytpmE .aivirT
.tsud fo sduolc pu gnikcik ,dnal nepo eht ssorca htrof dna kcab rotcart ssel-bac ,eulb a gnivird saw ehS   .ecein riehT
Ó.tsuguA ni reviled llÕI selab dnuoR
.mih saw tahT .elbisnopser
.redluohs sih ot nwod gnissik-elbbin
.reh ot kcab nehT
reksihw sih ot gnulc stelpord yartS
teertS niaM fo dne eht ta
,rebmemer dluoc eh emit tsrif eht roF
Ó?naem I ,worromoT ?pleh ym deeNÒ
.dlohesuoh tcirts a ni pu werg uoy teb I ,uoy ,woN
.emit siht ylluf erom ,niaga delims nosremE
Ó,taht yas dÕuoy wenk IÒ Ó.sseug IÒ
Ó.won ,srobhgien erÕew ,lla retfA
.enod erÕuoy dna pu ekaW Õ.og-ot-sliatÔ evah eciMÒ
.sdees eht gnieerf
Ó,ylenol erÕuoy timda ot yako sÕtIÒ
.rehtnap emit-lluf a
.llaf eht ni htiw etaroced ylevitsef ot selab dnuor gib gnitnaw syawla erew secalp Õtnemniat-irgaÔ dna sdrahcrO
Ó?eilrahC ,seYÒ Ó?ymmEÒ
,doof fo etalp a gnidloh ,nosremE
.gnirob noitnem ot toNÒ Ó?liat ruoYÒ
.sehctip etarepsed ,hgih ni gnikaeuqs ,tuo deirc eH
Ó.eruc gnizama siht tnetap dluohs eW !ssergorPÒ
.edis eht ot woble sselmrah a mih gnivig ,dias eilrahC
Ó.no kcab sehtolc ruoy tup ylbaborp dluohs uoYÒ
.retaw eci fo neetnac a morf delzzug eH
.reklat a sÕehs tuB
eno siht piks nac uoy
.rethgil hcum erew sklats niarg deird tub
É rof meÔ htiw ÕniyatSÒ Ó.hAÒ
.kcab langis tÕndid nosremE
.dehctiwt sreksihw siH Ó.sey É dnAÒ
ecalp azzip eht ot neeb ydaerla evÕdluow uoy ,wonk uoYÒ
,dlo sraey net ni sa
.esuom eht naht rellat saw ehs ,nwod gnittis nevE
Ó?kniht uoy tÕnoD .hguoht ,lamroFÒ
É pleh eht deen did eH .lleW
?rewopesroHÒ   .won roF
Ó.yas syob yhsulb eht lla tahw sÕtahTÒ
na evah ot demees ehS
Ó.niamod cilbup sÕtIÒ
?yllaeRÒ .llor taehw A
!yleritne wor eht gnissim saw tI
ecnalab sih ecnahne ot
.erutseg Õssik sÕfehcÔ a gnimim
.eil nwo sih ni pu thguac fi sa
.tcatnoc latnorf-lluf edam yehT
.ti gnirepsihw tsomla
,gniunitnoc ,wohs rof egadneppa yhsub reh deffulf lerriuqs ehT Ó É lleWÒ
Ó.detrats teg dluohs eWÒ
.kcab denael dna etalp repap no nwod ti tes ehs ,nroc fo rae reh htiw dehsiniF
Ó.lliks a saw ti wonk tÕndiDÒ
.sucof ot gniyrt ,detpurretni nosremE Ó,rotcart eht ni ydaerla sÕyek ehT .mU .yakOÒ
.ylthgil dias nosremE
.daehrevo delleporp senalpria ynit elihw
.reh ot kcab sih ,desuap nosremE
.ecaf reh no ytilibarenluv fo kool feirb a
Ó?ti tÕnsi ,yffuts adniK
Ó É tub ,haeY ?serauqs ehTÒ
tog tsuj tI .did reveNÒ
trac latem a morf
Õ.azziP egalliVÔ rof gnikool erÕuoY
.aes eht ot neeb reven dah nosremE
Ó?uoy tÕnod ,teem stnemele gnisoppo owt nehw sneppah tahw wonk uoYÒ Ó.ton erÕuoy dnAÒ
Ó!neht ,ti selttes tahTÒ
Ó!did ohw enoemos sa uoy deggep evÕdluow IÒ
.denetfos noisserpxe sÕnosremE   Ó.gniht
.eciov reh tuoba gnihtemoS
.emit siht yawa teg ot elba eb annog tÕnsaw eh dezilaer
.niaga dias nosremE Ó,sseug IÒ
.nrab eht yb ti gnikrap
.trihs reh tuoba kniht ot hsur a fo hcum oot ni saw ehS .oot ,seitnaP
.sehtolc sih otni kcab delggirw eh sa gnihsulb ,deohce eh Ó,thgiRÒ
.tsaf os deneppah tI
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil erÕuoY
,eno dehsinif ydaerla
leehw eht nups yllacitsaisuhtne eilrahC sa
.moc.yrrufos.lerriuqs ta seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
deohce lerriuqs eht
.evitcudorp leef rehtar dÕIÒ
.gniwonk ton ,daeh sih koohs nosremE
?ekil kool sruoy sÕtahW .emosewa
,dleif eht fo egde eht ot gnirutneV
.hgih sreyal ruof og ylno dluoc eH
wonk uoY .ti sÕtaht tub ,dloc dna nus morf tcetorp attog uoy ,eruS .mooB
.ylneve erom yrd dluow swor eht
Ó?evah ti seod rewopesroh hcum woHÒ
Ó,flesym ,emankcin a uoy evig ot evah annog mÕIÒ
.gnihtemos etacinummoc ot gniyrt fi sa ,rehtegot swap reh debbur ehS
.yltfos demriffa lerriuqs eht Ó,ti teg IÒ
,dedda dna desuap ehS
,deddon nosremE Ó?seirecorGÒ
.os did ehs sa Õpu sbmuhtÔ a mih dehsalf ehS
Ó?ffuts siht reviled attog eWÒ
.esoh eht morf dekaos llits erew yehT
etuhc raer sÕrelab eht tfel ti erofeb elab warts a barg ot drawrof dehsur esuom tsevrah eht ,thgirpu gnipeeK
,naem IÒ ,deremmats eH
Ó,ytilibail a ekil sleeFÒ
,005 ydnI eht rof yfilauq ot gniyrt saw ehs ekil evord eilrahC sA       Ó.nosaer oNÒ Ó?yhW
.emoh mÕI wonk yehT .rood txen evil I
,roloc noen thgirb emos sÕti teb I
Ó?ti tÕnsi ,elisneherp si sruoYÒ
.yllaer ,laedi eht si llaf tuBÒ
.ereht pu nuf hcum oot elttil a gnivah saw lerriuqs ehT
Ó.dloc oot steg ti nehw kcos-liat lamreht a raew ot evah I
,ecnartne tnorf eht yb trac eht gniruceS Ó?tahw htiWÒ
,neddibnu dias lerriuqs eht Ó,eilrahC mÕIÒ
.esion gnirettihc a edam ehS
.daeh reh evoba smra reh dehcterts ehS Ó.yrrow tÕnod tuB
.elpoep dnasuoht a naht ssel
,tfel eh fi eno txen eht ssim dÕeh gniwonK
.yks eht ni sduolc emos erew erehT
.tsrif ta gnihtyna dias stnedor gnirednaem eht fo rehtieN
.maerc dna hctocsrettuB
,ylsselpleh delims esuom ehT Ó?ymmE ,tey dexaleRÒ
.devom ehs woh fo suoicsnoc ylbidercni saw nosremE dna
.edahs suoiciled ,looc eht ni ,nus eht morf yawa edis ehT
.yllufyalp derumrum ehs Ó?sey a taht saWÒ
.ediskcab dna ,daeh ,sbmil nedlog sih ot tsartnoc yranoitcefnoc a dereffo ylleb dna tsehc sih fo etihw ehT
,elab rehtona debbarg nosremE
.mih no esoh eht gninrut ylsuoenatnops ,desaet eilrahC Ó?ta gnikool uoy era tahWÒ
.reh egdelwonkca tÕndid nosremE nehw ,dias eilrahC
.rehtie ,rednels sa toN .sehcni wef a yB
.ssarg remmus ,hsul eht otno
.ydob ehtil sih revo dettilf seye sÕeilrahC
,srettuhs rewolfnus dna gnidis eulb thgirb htiW .enola devil eH
.mih ediseb ydaerla
.noziroh eht ta derutseg ehS Ó É ro nwot ehTÒ
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,dehgis dna deppots esuom eht
,dekaeuqs nosremE
.kcurt sih fo kcab eht otni dereep ehS
Ó.oNÒ Ó?emankcin a toGÒ
Ó.nuf on sÕtaht ,lleWÒ .dias eh
.emit gnitsaw potS
.gnilab reisae rof dengila yltaen
.yletelpmoc ffo sreh dekcik lerriuqs ehT
?detagilbo eh tÕnsaW
.mih dewollof eilrahC
Ó É huh-hUÒ .yllacidarops dekcilf liat deggol-retaw reH
.rettam eht no yas ot esle tahw erusnu ,deddon nosremE
.wap rehto reh htiw esoh eht fo dne eht pu gnikcip
.wap reh htiw erutseg Õno os ,no osÔ a edam ehS
ÓÑteg dluohs I ,lleW .thgiRÒ .deretnuoc ehs
.tsehc erab sih nwod regnif a decart lerriuqs ehT
Ó.tuoba klat ot gnihtyna evah tÕndid uoy dias uoy dnAÒ .delggig ehS
,pu wor htruof eht ot daeh sih revo ti gnissot dna gnixelf
Ó.tsevrah ot ydaer si dleif taehw yM .sÕnisuoc a sÕtI
Ó.ydaerla nwod tis tsuJ
Ó,ciloh-a-krow a erÕuoy esuac sÕtahTÒ Ó.evitcudorp
.lerriuqs fo epyt elbigirrocni yllaicepse nA .slerriuqs xoF
.detsisni lerriuqs eht
.enot ytrilf a no koot eciov reH
.dengila ylguns erew yeht erus ekam ot meht gnihsup dna gnikcik
Ó?tnaw uoy od tahW
,deilper eh Ó,etal oot sraey noillib a erÕew kniht IÒ
,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer
.gnikcats ot ygetarts a saw erehT
Ó?doog siht sliat htiw deb fo tuo poh tsuj slerriuqs kniht uoy oD
?setunim neetfif ,tahw ,ekat llÕtIÒ
,thgil noonretfa-etal eht nI
?he Õ,gnirednawÔ ekil eroMÒ
.dnuora puenil elohw eht denrut dna
.tnemesuma htiw dias eilrahC Ó?tahw roFÒ Ó.yrroSÒ
?gninrom yreve gniht siht gnimoorg dneps attog I gnol woh
?sdoow eht ni srrub-ykcits esoht pu skcip ro
egailof tuc fo senil tcnitsid
.derretednu saw eilrahC
.rehto hcae gniltserw nageb yeht ,dnuorg eht ot deppils ti nehW
.tops eht no detlem tsomla eH
.hctarcs morf nrael attog evÕuoy ,oSÒ
taehw ykips fo retsulc a hguorht wap knip ,sselruf a nar nosremE
.ygrene fo llew sseldne
.mra hcae ni elab enO
Ó.yllis tsuj sÕtahT
Ó?robhgien ,Õniod uoy tahWÒ
.won dna ereh eht
.yarps eht yb ffo tuc sdrow sih ,dekaeuqs nosremE ÓÑhtoNÒ
Ó?elihw a tiaw tÕnac tIÒ
.rail elbirret a mÕI noitnem ot toN
.remraf a erÕuoy nehW ?he ,llaf dna remmus eht ni ysub os teg sgniht É tsuj sÕtI .syad ynnus ,mraw ekil I ,naem IÒ .deunitnoc eilrahC Ó,hguoht ,erutarepmet eht neve ton sÕtIÒ   Õ.llew ,hoÔ
.nrab der eht ot dennip reh gnipeek
?dnats elcispop siht wolb annaW .yeHÒ
Ó?od ot krow erom evah tÕnod uoy erus uoYÒ Ó?edisni og annaWÒ
,ylisae ffo emac tI
,enod erew yeht nehW
,dias eh ,etalp sih no nwod llor sih gnittuP
.niaga nwod deyarps eb ot deen I ebyaM
.gnihtemos ro ytiretsop roF .wodniw eht ni egangis eht fo trap tfel yehT
ylliSÒ Ó.yllis erÕyehTÒ
Ó.mmh-mMÒ Ó?thgiR .hguoht ,dab toNÒ .detnap nosremE
Ó,won thgir yrgnuh yllaer ton mÕIÒ
,dias ,noisserpxe suoiruc sih gniees ,eilrahC .lacol tÕnsaW
tixe kciuq a ekam yltcaxe tÕndluoc nosremE
?he ,pu werg uoy woh no sdnepeDÒ
É ot nuf erom ,denigami eh ,dnA
.daeh sih gnitlit ,dewehc nosremE
dÕI em dlot enoyreve ,regnuoy saw I nehWÒ
.demialcxe ehs Ó!gnitaehc sÕtaht ,riaf oNÒ
,yltfos deksa ehs ,tnemom a retfA .delggig eilrahC
.roivaheb eht tcerroc ot sselpleh
,niarg eht gnitsevrah retfA .tsal ,yllufknaht
.dednopser ehs Ó,doof knuj evol IÒ
,ereh tnapicitrap evissap a sa nevE
.deirrow lla ta ton ,deilper eilrahC
.teerts eht ssorca gnippiks lerriuqs xof eht ees ot denrut esuom tsevrah ehT .eilrahC
yletelpmoc ,esuom ehT .gel a gnitfil
yas ot fi sa daeh sih gnikahs dna tib a gnilggirw
,ssentew reh htiw gninetsilg
.dehctiwt nosremE Ó.sesucxEÒ Ó?tahWÒ
.tseretni esol dÕehs gnipoh ,laem sih gnitae deunitnoc tsuj nosremE .dediced eilrahC
Ó,gnirednow erÕuoy tahw sÕtaht fi ,etib tÕnod IÒ
.reh morf ssorca tis ot rehtehw detabed
.denrub sraE .decar traeh siH
Ó,mmh-mMÒ Ó.ti fo tuo gnitteg mÕI gnittuc ylno eht sÕtaht os ,taehw launna saw tI
.htuom sih otni wef a deppop eh
.serauqs rellams eht ni detseretni erom erew secalp nedraG
.dehsulb esuom ehT
.tuo decra retaw eht sa spil reh ot esolc ti tup ehS
.demrifnoc yllautneve eilrahC Ó,tcartta yehTÒ
,swordniw eht gnitrevni ,rotcart eht dniheb dellup gnieb saw ekar der A
Ó.nees evÕI É hu ,evÕI ,haeYÒ
tahw wonk uoYÒ Ó.ynapmoc ot edutilos gnirreferp siÒ
.esuoh sih ot ,redluohs sih revo dekool esuom ehT Ó?pan a ebyaM
,dias lerriuqs eht Ó,ytsriht mÕIÒ
Ó.tluciffid ton mÕIÒ
saw sihT      Ó.tiaw nac tIÒ
.did eh ,ho ,dnA .reh ot dnA
Ó?ydaerla emoh gniog uoYÒ
.dettimda eilrahC Ó,remmus ot retniw referp IÒ
Ó?uoy htiw emit erom dneps ot deganam evah I dluow woh nehTÒ
Ó,gniyas a tsuj saw Õesuom a sa teiuqÔ thguoht IÒ
Ó?ezirp a teg I oDÒ
.daeh sih koohs dna delims nosremE Ó!elbaroda
.rehtegot desserp seidoB
.dewollaws nosremE
.ekips erutarepmet sih tlef ,dias dÕeh tahw gnizilaer ,nosremE .demaeb eilrahC
Ó.enim ot derapmoc É mu
.debbir ehs Ó,ngised eyd-eit ykcaw a ebyam ro
.os gniod ot dengiser ,deddon nosremE
.ylesuforp dehsulb sraE !dekaeuqs eH
.dennirg lerriuqs ehT
,detaes ylluF Ó?sseug IÒ
.niaga rehto hcae otni pmub llÕeWÒ
É tub ,haeYÒ .dias lerriuqs eht
Ó,yaw taht tnemetats a ekam tÕnaC .ooBÒ
.emit ni tsuj flesmih thguac tub taht ot Õsseug IÔ dias tsomla nosremE
,gniksa erofeb thguoht fo niart reh tsol ehS Ó.oS .mMÒ
.ecim ot derapmoC
dÕyehT .nogaw rep selab derdnuh A
,spih sih dnuora htob meht depparw ehS
.detliw sreksihw siH
,seye eulb sih desolc esuom tsevrah ehT
Ó.won ,htnom a rof ereh neeb evÕuoY ?ecalp siht fo kniht uoy od tahw É hu ,tahWÒ
Ó?taht morf knird I naCÒ
.taehw fo dleif a deyevrus nosremE ,dessorc smrA
Ó,nosremE mÕI .hOÒ
Ó.oiratnO morf mÕIÒ
,ho É ti potS !hah-
Ó.ees llÕeW .onnud I ?regnol ebyam
.slerriuqs redlo owT
lluf erew selbat rehto eht fo tsoM
Ó,elbigirrocni erÕuoYÒ
.tae ot etib a dnA
,aedi eht ta suoicsnoc-fles yltnatsni ,esuom ehT
.esle gnihtemos tnalP .won ,pu taht wolp attoGÒ
Ó?ycilop nruter eht sÕtahWÒ
.kcurt eht ot kcab dna lerriuqs eht tsap teg ot gniyrt ,evom a edam esuom ehT
,dekan yletelpmoc llits ,nosremE Ó.em llet uoYÒ
.tuhs meht gnippiz ,pu strohs reh dellup ehS
.reh ot elbaroda wohemos saw ÕyesuomÔ gnihtyrevE
É hhhOÒ Ó.taht erofeb sraey derdnuh a revo rof yrarbil dlo eht dah ew tub
Ó.enituor Õlaicos-itnaÔ siht htiw ffo em eracs ot gniog ton erÕuoYÒ
.liat reh ot deyarts noitnetta siH
,htob meht dekcats nosremE ,tsud fo duolc a ni nogaw eht fo kcab eht ot gnilffuhS
Ó,setunim net tsap eht rof gniklat neeb evÕeWÒ
H !hAÒ .egnar knalb-tniop ta reh gniyarps ,tnew eh Ó?ohw syaSÒ
.puc dna etalp ytpme sih gnibbarg
.si ti toh woh tuoba gniknihTÒ
.gnilgnat sreksihw ,spil eht nO
.esuoh Õsrobhgien eht ta saw esuom tsevrah ehT .eno otni depor saw eh fi )nalp sih saw hcihw(
.ecar otua na no tes ,ylduol
.dliub ydruts ,dilos A
Ó?ommE tuobÔ woH !ho
,keehc sih no detnap eilrahC
.epuolatnac fo sknuhC
Ó.neeb evah syawlAÒ
Ó.ti yub tÕndid uoy emussAÒ Ó.puYÒ Ó.ycnaFÒ
Ó?uoy tÕnera ,ylimaf eht fo trap erÕuoYÒ
Ó,em wonk erus uoYÒ
.wonk uoy É tsuj sÕtIÒ
.sih ni swap sÕeilrahC koot dna daeh sih koohs nosremE
.edisni reh gniwollof ,dehgis nosremE
,niaga delggig eilrahC
.seye eht ni eilrahC dekool eh
.ot dednet erew sdray sa deohce sdnuos rewomnwaL
.neht ytterp os toN
.sgab gnippohs esoht ni maerc eci evah uoy sselnU .no emoC
ÓÑnaem siht seod É mu ,oSÒ
.detaes gniniamer ,ylnialp
.mih retfa dellac eilrahC
Ó,ni gid yeht nehw elbaroda os era eciM
,no oidar a dah enoemoS
Ó!dloc os sÕti sÕwoh ,hsog ym
.smsaps ni ,mih dnuora dehcnelc xes reH
esuoM .T dleiF yb
.snoitativni rieht enilced ot etilop oot syawla saw nosremE
.erutseg reh gniwollof ,detniuqs nosremE Ó.desolc sÕti tuBÒ
.demihc lleb A .nepo ti gnillup
.taeh esnetni dna nus rof dellac tsacerof egnar-trohs ehT
.detsisni eh Ó,enituor a ton sÕtIÒ
.seitimertxe sih leef ot elba yldrah
,lacitcarp eht no desucof esuom eht ,gninepoer seyE
Ó.lacov fo dnik gnieb erew uoy ,lleWÒ
dimit gnieb ,ekil ,si ÕyhsÔ É mu ,lleWÒ
.ommE dellac o-esuom a eb tÕnaC .haNÒ ,dias ehs ,flesreh gnirewsnA
?dessim eb ti dluoc woH
,gnizilaicos ,ynapmoc gnivol ,strevortxe latot erew slerriuqs xof ehT .tuokooc rehtona
?dneirfyob wen a evah I tahTÒ
Ó.ereht meht teg I ecno snogaw eht daolnu ot elpoep evah yehTÒ
Ó?ti si ,pu hctiws ot eman ysae na ton
.esoh eht htiw deltserw dna delggig yehT Ó!erad uoy tÕnoDÒ
Ó?ti tÕnsi ,krad-eht-ni-wolg sÕtIÒ
Ó.tuoba klat ot hcum evah tÕnod I tuB .reffo eht rof sknaht
,lleWÒ Ó.revetahw ,wonk uoy
Ó,won ,dray ruoy ni enibmoc a tog evÕuoy waSÒ
.gnap lanretni ,prahs a gnileef ,dnuora denrut nosremE
.mih ta detniuqs eilrahC
.em evoba gnirewot niatnuom a ekil sÕti ,semitemoSÒ
Ó,ton diarfa mÕI ,on É mÕIÒ
,dna dnoces eht saw sihT
,mih dlot ehs Ó,hguoht ,liat esuom a fo citehtsea naelc ,elpmis eht taeb tÕnaCÒ
.nrab eht fo edistuo eht tsniaga depmuls nosremE
.ylimaf eht tpecxE .ereh enoyna wonk tÕnod IÒ
Ó.ylniagnu eb ot flesruoy gniveileBÒ
.demrifnoc eh Ó,sey ,esuom a ma IÒ
.flesmih deppots tub ÕylenolÔ dias tsomla eH
.rehtnap emit-lluf a
,tilc reh ta gnibbur detrats eilrahC
Ó.adanaC ni sÕtahTÒ .esuap A
.yaw sÕnus eht ni teg ot hsur on ni erew yeht
.trihs-t sih fo tuo delggirw nosremE
,deunitnoc ehs ,rewsna tÕndid eh nehW Ó?lareneg nIÒ
.dekcod teg dluow tnemyap sih ro tnecrep neetfif rednu detset eb ot dah tI
.noitnetta reh teg ot gniyrt ,eilrahC ta smra sih devaw yllacitnarf eH
.deknay eh ,sregnif sih htiw eno gnilcricnE .sdaeh-
Ó?ksa uoy dÕyhw nehTÒ Ó.gnihtoNÒ
.dehctiwt sreksihw sÕnosremE .dias eilrahC
?yeht tÕnerew ,srotagitsni syawla erew slerriuqs ,neht tuB
.nroc teews deroloc-ib fo rae demaets a no gniwang
.kcen sih gnigguh smra
.derednow eilrahC
,ti fo tuo deppans yllanif ehs ,srorrim eht ni esuom eht ta gnikwaG
.toh tog skeehc siH
,reh otni denael ,dekan
sreksihw reh ffo delbmut slenrek wolley dna etihW
,naem I É sÕtaht
.swap-toof reh fo spit eht no gnicnuob ,desuap lerriuqs ehT Ó!thgiR .yako
,ecalp tsrif eht ni noitasrevnoc ekam ot gnivah fo ssendrawkwa eht morf edisA   .llet nac I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,mih rof yletanutrofnu ,tuB
.elbat eht no swoble
yaw hcihw yreve gnippihw liat elisneherp ,ypor ,seenk sih tneb esuom ehT
ÓÑdna dloc dna krad os sÕtI .od nac uoy sgniht reweF
.snoitaler regnuoy rieht fo enO
.sregnif reh dnuora liat ypor sih fo pit eht gnipparw ,delggig eilrahC
.dleif taehw ytpme eht ta tuo dezag nosremE
?keew A ?syad erom eviF
Ó.mraf sÕelcnu dna tnua ym si sihTÒ
.railimaf os demees dÕehs yhw dezilaer ylneddus osla eH
.tnemom yna ta sredluohs reh ffo edils ot denetaerht sparts eulb ehT
Ó?detrevortni dna yhs neewteb ecnereffid eht sÕtahWÒ
Ó?ot desoppus I mAÒ
,gnihtemos no elbbin dna pu wohs yllausu dÕeH
.dnuorg eht ot llef dna
.spih reh fo ecnedac ehT
.gnilaeppa saw msaisuhtne reh timda dluoc nosremE
Ó!dehsiugnitsid yreV
.detaeper nosremE
,nwot Õthgilpots onÔ ypeels a saw sihT
.ta si ecalp eht erehw wonk tÕnod I ,ylnO .azzip kcab gnirb ot nwot otni em tnes elcnu dna tnua ,lleWÒ
,meht gnitator yB
.tuoba deggalf liat eH
.dias eilrahC Ó,si liat ruoy ecnanetniam-wol woh etaicerppa tÕnod uoYÒ .nuf eroM .llew
?azzip tae od uoy tuBÒ
,pu doots dna htaerb peed a koot esuom ehT
yllacitahpme deddon
.ylhtooms deretnuoc lerriuqs eht
tfahs knip kciht sih was dna nwod dekool eh litnu tÕnsaw tI .tnegru oS
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
Ó.yakOÒ Ó.suovren dna
si yrots sÕyadoT dna
.pu reh dleh eh sa dnuorg eht ffo yletelpmoc saw ehS
.esnetni os saw ,siht rof ,reh rof deen eht ,tsul dna erised ehT
.yltcaxe ,meht ton ,lleW
É ees sÕteLÒ .tÕndid ehS
.ecnelis eht ekorb dna taorht sih deraelc esuom nedlog ehT
.gnihtemos fo kniht llÕIÒ
?etilop oot erÕuoy esuaCÒ
.dessorc dah yeht dlohserht eht dedneherpmoc ylluf eh taht
.noitativni reh tpecca ot flesmih gnirb tÕndluoc eh ,sseldrageR É ylenol ton mÕI
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.gnisaet saw ehs gnitacidni ,delggig lerriuqs ehT    .dluoc ylbaborp ehs gniwonk ,dehctiwt sreksihw sÕnosremE
.ylnrobbuts dias esuom eht Ó,esuaceBÒ .desserp eilrahC
.gniggurhs ,desuap nosremE
Ó.em gnilssah tÕnerew uoy fiÑkcab dnaÑ
.emac ehs sa dekrab ehS
.rehtegot klawedis eht nwod gniklaw htob erew yeht ,retal etunim A
,wap knip ,sselruf sih hcuot ot noitom evislupmi na edam eilrahC
era sgniht esoht ,hsog ym ,hOÒ
.llew lluf wenk nosremE
Ó,yb og enoyna raeh tÕndid IÒ
emas eht skniht esle gnihtyreve fi gnirednow dnAÒ
,remmus elohw eht
.esuoM .T dleiF yb
,ydob nwo sih edistuo morf flesmih gnihctaw ekil saw ti tub ,ti gniod saw eh erawa saw eH
Ó?gidnihs siht ta uoy era yhw
.rehtegot swap yerg-hsinworb reh gnipsalc ,dias ehs Ó!etaciled os erÕuoYÒ
,emit ni tsuj eniwt eht deggans eH
.elbat eht ot resolc riahc sih detoocs nosremE
,gniyas elbatrofmoc tlef esuom eht
.desaet lerriuqs eht
.ylwols deddon eH .deknilb nosremE
Ó.taob emas eht ni erÕeWÒ Ó É mUÒ
,ssarg ro aflafla htiw taht deirt dÕeh fi kcab sih tuo nworht evÕdluow yletinifed eH
.niart a fo esoobac eht pota fi sa
.deyarf erew strohs mined reH .htob ebyaM
.thgis ni ciffart oN
,deunitnoc eh Ó,ÕnoisrevortnIÔÒ
.ydob gnilliw sih edaussid ot dnim deldda sih rof etal oot saw ti neht yb tuB
,sreh gnidiova seyE
,delbmum esuom eht
.os dias enoyrevE
.enelrahC sÕeman laeRÒ
.stcnitsni sih ot bmuccus ot mih gniggeb ,delgnit ydob elohw siH
,yek-wol ,dednuorG
ydob reh otni gniraeppasid
Ó.selur eht ekam tÕnod I !esuaceBÒ Ó?yhWÒ Ó!seYÒ
ÓrooD txeN lerriuqS ehTÒ   :yojne esaelP
.no kcab ti nrut ot deirt dna reh dewollof nosremE
.gel rehto eht tfil reh gnittel ,pmur reh gnippirg swap
Ó?meht ecrofne tsuj uoY .ees IÒ
Ó?rood txen evil ot sneppah eh dnA
.yzoc dna tniauq fo noitinifed eht saw gnidliub yrots-eno eht
,yltneconni derepsihw nosremE
ÕwenÔ ,lleW .yrarbil wen eht yB
.krims a htiw dias ehs
.esruoc no kcab meht teg ot leehw eht gninrut dna taes reh ni pu gnipmuj
,gnidda ,taeb a deppiks ehS
.gniworruf worb ,desuap ehS
.feihcsim ro thgilnus morf gnilkraps seye eulb peed
.tsrif eht ot ralucidneprep ruof
.ylireehc dereffo eilrahC
.daor eht ssorca detniop eH
Ó.yawa og dÕti ,wonk uoy
deunitnoc eilrahC Ó,ereh morf esuoh ruoy ees yllacitcarp nac IÒ
.meht fo eno dettops nosremE
.ti yned tÕndid lerriuqs ehT
.reh otni pmub ot mih gnisuac ,mih dewodahs ehS
Ó.pu uoy taeb ot evah annaw tÕnod IÒ
.elims dehtootkcub ,ysae na dehsalf eilrahC
Ó,tnemilpmoc a sa taht ekat dluohs uoYÒ
Ó.tsewdiM eht ni taht ekil era sremmuSÒ Ó.dimuh woH
.nehw kcab yaw ,ecalp azzip a ot desu tI .yteicos lacirotsih eht sÕtahT .hOÒ
.thgiarts pu tas eilrahC
.kcab daeh reh dessot dna depsag yllautneve eilrahC
,deremmats dna htuom sih denepo tsuj eH .kcolb latnem a ekil saw tI
.reh morf yawa esoh eht hctans ot liat sih desu dna swap sih htiw seye sih dedleihs esuom eht ,gnihguaL Ó!yeH !keEÒ
.pots tÕndluoc eH .xelfer a tsomla saw tseretni sÕrehtona tcelfed ot ytiliba ehT
.dedaog lerriuqs eht Ó,no emoCÒ
ekam annog uoYÒ .don a htiw dias eilrahC Ó,thguoht I ,roloc thgir eht tuoba dekooLÒ
.taht ekil ffuts drieW .tcatnoc eye
.esirprus ni worb a dekriuq eilrahC Ó?tahWÒ
.kcurt pukcip derehtaew sih fo deb desopxe eht otni meht tes dna
.tnemevom fo modeerf ssel sÕereht tub ,haeYÒ
.daeh sih koohs nosremE
.erutsiom tnaem hcihW .tfos ooT
yawa kcolb a ylsuoyoj dekeirhs yalp ta nerdlihC
.nrab eht fo renroc eht ta togips latem ,der a ot gnitniop ,deksa eilrahC
.kooh eht ffo mih gnittel ,deksa lerriuqs eht
Ó.selbategev ruoy taE .serohc ruoy oD
.yadot no sllarevo dah ehS
Ó.detrevortni É tsuj mÕIÒ
.aes detrevni na no sdnalsi yzal ,seno yffulf ,giB
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I dna
.redraoh ytilibisnopser a saw eH
.sucof sih niager ot gniyrt ,gniknilb ,deffuh nosremE
ÓrooD txeN lerriuqS ehTÒ
.sesucxe ekam ot gniunitnoc ,dias eh
.rewohs a htiw od dluoc eWÒ
Ó?he ,gniwolPÒ .yldetcartsid
Ó?ekil dnuos esoht
?ti tÕnsi ,ti sÕtahT
,htaerb peed a gnikat ,nosremE Ó.wonk I
É tuoba em llet ,dnuora em wohs nac uoY .dworc eht morf yawa uoy teg dÕtIÒ
,bonk eht denrut dna rood tnorf sih dehcaer eh sa tuB .syawlA
,derumrum ehs ,sih ot eson reh gnihcuot dna daeh reh gnitfiL
.desucca esuom eht
Ó?mmh ,tuo em pleh dluoc uoy ebyaMÒ Ó.haeYÒ
,esuoM .T dleiF yb ÓrooD txeN lerriuqS ehTÒ
Ó É daor eht morf su was eno on epoh IÒ
.detsisni nosremE
Ó,ruoh na koot ylno tahTÒ .spit-
.niaga reh dessik dna
.deleviws srae siH
?meht fo owt eht tsuJ ?reh htiW ?klaw A
.reh truh dah noitcejer sih llet dluoc nosremE Ó.lleW .yakÕMÒ
.htaerb peed a koot nosremE
É os enod dÕeh sa delggig dah eilrahC
É naem uoY .hO ?oloSÒ
.ffahc eht fo tsom delab dnuor dÕeh
.deleviws srae yhsid siH Ó!ymmEÒ
yaws dna eltsur porc eht ot gninetsil
,ylippah derettihc ehS Ó.taht ekil ,sey
.ylthgil delims nosremE
.erots lareneg eht
Ó?tfel sÕtahw fo tuo warts
.daeh reh gnitlit ,deksa eilrahC Ó?olos nur uoYÒ
,thgiew sih lla htiw reh otni denael nosremE
?kramer suoitatrilf a saw taht fi derednow nosremE
,ynapmoc tnaw tÕndid uoy fIÒ
.aflaflA .tsud yaH
Ó.ereht gnitteg eb thgim IÒ
.detsisni eh Ó,si ti erehw wonk IÒ
Ó.enoemos dnif llÕIÒ
.pu reyal txen eht redro eht desrever uoy neht dnA .lla ni eviF
.kcams a htiw trapa dellup yehT
,mih ta delims ehS Ó!puYÒ
.sreh htiw dekcol seye sÕnosremE
.erugif sÕlerriuqs eht nwod dna pu dettilf ezag siH
,pals drawpu ,kcils a htiw
Ó.stif ti fi eeS .no ti yrt tsuJÒ
,ybigreK yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots sÕyadoT
.tcejbus eht gnignahc ,dias lerriuqs eht
.spih sih ot ti tfil ot mra eno gnisu
É kcab skeew wef a reh tem dÕeh nehw gnirebmemer
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.ylhtooms dias ehs
Ó?ti sIÒ Ó.etuc sÕti ,haeYÒ
É tub ,mraf a no pu werg dna dne esool a ta mÕI .pleh emos deen dna
.edanomel fo pis a koot eh
Ó?ebyam ,klaw a rof oG
.tekcop sih ni ti deffuts dna ffo ti deknay eH .ti ot thguoht on saw erehT
?ylenol mÕI dias ohW
Ó.o-esuom ,em naht reision erew uoYÒ
É mMÒ .potelbat eht no spit-walc reh demmurd lerriuqs ehT
.ti od dluow tahT
.srobhgien eht morf ytreporp sih detarapes enil-ecnef nedoow ,etihw A
.liat derruf a evah uoy esuaceb ylbaborp sÕtahTÒ
.hcaer fo tuo tsuj ti tpek nosremE tub
.selkna sih dnuora gnitcelloc snaej ,dewollof nosremE .tsrif stnap reh deppord eilrahC
.emocni ym evoba yaW .on ,haeYÒ
.devaeh tsehc erab sÕnosremE
?ekil sdnuos naeco eht tahw siht sI .ezeerb eht ni
.pu gnittel ton ,detsisni ehs Ó,ffo gnilooc deen uoy ekil kool uoYÒ
É trihs taht htaeneb gnihtyna gniraew sÕehs kniht tÕnod I
,drawpu ti deggut ylwols dna eldnah eht deppirg eilrahC sa dehctaw esuom ehT
.gnivael ylteercsid erofeb yrehpirep eht no gnirewolf-llaw
.serihppas ekil erew yehT
.ytreporp sih drawot derutseg ehS
.tols thgir eht otni ti hcnup ot pu gnipmuj
?klaw a em ewOÒ ÓÑhu ,IÒ
.tniuqs luferac a htiw mih gniyduts ,devresbo eilrahC
Ó!wonk uoy ,rotcart a evird nac IÒ
.thguoht yrev eht ta gnirevihs ,deohce nosremE Ó?retniWÒ
.gnikcats tpek nosremE
Ó!em no ti esu ton retteb uoy os ,si ti ,lleWÒ
.sevruc reh fo snoitaludnu ehT
,nrab eht fo edis eht tsniaga kcab denael ehs sa no deniamer tI
.ffo ti denrut dna togips eht ot dekcartkcab lerriuqs reggib ehT
Ó.syad eseht mraf ylimaf a sa ti ekam ot draHÒ
.daeh sih koohs dna taorht sih deraelc esuom tsevrah ehT Ñylbatceled
,taehw sih fo sutats eht gnikcehc retfa syad wef a ,yltneserP
.ylsuoenatlumis rehto eht debbarg dna detiaw eh
,ragus dna nomannic fo erutxim mraw a ekil dewolg ti ,nus eht ni gnirettulF
.dias eilrahC Ó?drawkwAÒ Ó É erom
Ó É yhs eb ot etuc sÕti skniht enoyrevEÒ
Ó.srieht uoy dlot evÕyeht retfa eman ruoy nosrep a llet ot seiteicos tsom ni yramotsuc sÕti É wonk uoYÒ
.detniuqs eilrahC
Ó.eibeerf a ti redisnoCÒ
,gnilbmert ,reh edisni gnitlih erofeb regnol tib a tnew nosremE
Ó.owt eht fo xim tcefreP
.nwod neetnac sih tes eh ,gniknird enoD
,drawrof denael eilrahC
Ó.pleh deen llÕuoYÒ Ó.esruoCÒ
.aera eht ni sevitaler fo tol a evah I ,llew
.krof citsalp a htiw doof sih ta gnikop
Ó,maerc eci tae tÕnod IÒ Ó.tlem llÕti nehT
É seYÒ .no mih gnigru
.ruf sih ot euh ralimis a erob atsiv nedlog ,talf eht
,ygrene dna emit fo tol a sekat ti tuB
.llaw nedoow eht ta ydob sih neewteb gnihcra
.reh dnuora sriahc ytpme lareves dah ehs dna
Ó É ydnah ni semoc taht teBÒ
.reh gniretne rebmemer tÕndid nosremE
.deporg dna debbarg swaP
.oot ,nac yllanif uoy ,tnamrod seog ti nehW .dnal eht ot deit os erÕuoY
?tuoba klat yeht dluow tahW ?gnol woh roF ?erehW
sgab gnippohs citsalp derrefsnart esuom eht
,swap sih fo htob neewteb sniarg eht dellor dna klats eht ffo daeh eht ekorb eH
,nwot ni saw nosremE
,ylsselhtaerb detnap eilrahC
.ezag sih treva tÕndluoc nosremE
.ylevisnefed deksa eh Ó?trap hcihWÒ
.ssarg eht ot rewol swap-toof reh gnittel
.dias eh Ó,ereh ssorc ,hu ,nac eWÒ .azziP egalliV
.siht ekil noonretfa yadnuS a no reipeels nevE
Ó.no eno evah tÕnod I ekil skool ti oS .seno deroloc-hself eht raew I ,oNÒ
,yawa sirbed eht yrrac ezeerb eht gnitteL
,ti dloh ot fi sa
.elbat eht ot kcab gnirewol smra
,ecalp azzip eht ot rood eht dehcaer ehS
Ó.sdnuos esoht fo emos ekam dluoc slerriuqs wonk neve tÕndid IÒ
ÓÑtrep taht ot pu thgir seye eht sdael taht enilthgis denifed ,tcerid AÒ
.nodnaba htiw reh depmuh eh sa tniap emos ffo deparcs yehT
?eseehc ekil tÕnod uoy esuaceb ti sIÒ
.tcejbus eht gnignahc ,dennirg eilrahC Ó É oN ?tahWÒ
Ó.ti tuohtiw enasni og dÕuoY
Ó.hguoht ,uoy gniteem ecin saw tIÒ .dehsulb eH
.pu yaw eht no rehtaew eht no gnidnepeD .eruS ?ti elacs I naC
.riahc gnidlof a tuo dellup eH
Ó,naciremA na roF !evisserpmIÒ
.ssensuoicerp eht ta skeehc reh no swap reh gnisserp ,decnuonna eilrahC
.ti htiw klats ffits eht gnignirb
.kcen sih ta debbur ylyhs nosremE
tÕndid eilrahC Ó.weiv eht yojne ot pot eht ot teg I nehw detsuahxe oot mÕI dna
,deunitnoc nosremE os ,tpurretni
.llor taehw a fo segde eht delbbin esuom ehT
.wolgretfa htiw thgil
Ó.gnihctac-eye erom si sruoY
Ó.tluciffid gnieb peeK .no oGÒ
Ó,ylnOÒ .dias eilrahC
.dias eh Ó,teg I sa dexaler sa si sihTÒ Ó.o-esuom ,xaleRÒ
.dias nosremE Ó,hguoht ,won ytterp sÕtIÒ Ó.neht
.liat sih htiw esuoh sih ta detniop eH Ó É hu ,I É IÒ
Ó?terces esuom elbirroh ruoy taht sI
.doolb htiw hsulf srae sih gnileef ,deilper nosremE Ó,ytpme sÕneetnac ym É hu ,yMÒ
Ó,etuc ton ton sÕti ,naem IÒ
,esuom eht ta dereep ehs ,elbat drac erauqs a ta riahc gnidlof a no detaeS
.dees sih htiw egassap reh dellif eh sa gnislup ,dekrej dna depmuj tfahs siH
,sdik evah tÕnod ,redlo Õgnitteg erÕyehTÒ
Ó?wonkÕy ,ti dlos stnerap
.meht deifsitas yllausU
dettam ro tew steg ti nehw sneppah tahw wonk uoy dnAÒ
,relab dna rotcart a dniheb nogaw nedoow ytekcir gnivom a no doots nosremE ,retal syaD
.retaw raelc fo cra dloc ,gnorts a htiw mih deyarps ehs ,gninepo eht revo bmuht reH
Ó É sredistuo gnicarbme ta era sklof larur dab woh wonk uoY
?ehs tÕndid ,tnecca na dah ehS
É dna ,erom snoitautis laicos ni flesym tup ot dedeen tsuj I tahT Õ.ti fo tuo worgÔ
.snaeb neerg ,eloressac nroC
gnivah erew yehT
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
.tuhs deppals rood neercs A
.ehtaerb ot ecnahc a si retniW
.dehgual lerriuqs ehT
.ti ot dehcatta saw esoh nedrag neerg ,trohs A
.gniwohs hteetkcub
fo tol gnikrap eht ni
.deilper esuom eht
,emos teg ot tnew lerriuqs ehT
Ó,gnihtyna gnirednow tÕnsaw IÒ
.od ot sgniht erew erehT
Ó.retaw llew deretlifnu tsuj sÕtI .tnaw uoy fI .eruSÒ
,sreh detcarter lerriuqs ehT
.ruf-daeh sih hguorht wap a nar esuom ehT
.elims a decrof eilrahC Ó.og attog IÒ
.H latipac a htiW .toh saw tI
,elbat eht morf yawa devom eh sa gnippirt ylraen ,dias nosremE
,relab eht ot kcab og ot denrut esuom eht nehW
.yadot toN ?worromoTÒ
.enot gnosgnis a ni desimorp ehs Ó,emos evah uoy tel llÕI ?skcitsdaerb dnA
.tuo gnihtyna gninruhc tÕnsaw ti deciton eh
dna reh fo tuo gnillup yltneg
.dedda ehs Ó,yhs dnAÒ
.etisoppo eht saw eh ,gnihtyna fI
.nihc sih deppid ylerumed esuom ehT
Ó?ymmEÒ Ó.ymmE !ti tog IÒ
.daeh sih ni seitilibissop eht delgguj
.esuohmraf sih ot kcab deklaw nosremE ,sdees gniniamer eht gnissoT
.detrats dÕyeht erofeb liat dna srae sih ot neercsnus deilppa ylsuoreneg dÕeH
,tuB .tnempiuqe erahS .tuo rehto hcae pleh eW .snisuoC
.puc citsalp ytpme-won sih ni eci eht deiduts esuom ehT