taht dias ton ti sI“ ”.moolb reven dna
.enog saw dniw eht dnA
erifpmac sih dnuora emac yeht dnA
,gniveirg morf tser evah uoY
,ti ta kool ot retaw eht ni denrut srehto ehT
?eb ti dluow tahw ,esoprup yna esoohc dluoc uoht fI“ .legnA eht dias
snool eht ot tnew nam ehT
,dnal ffo raf a ni sdeed citsatnaf emos fo uoy sllet relletyrots a fI .uoy kooL
”?wonk yam yeht spahrep ,esirnus eht ro
dna denmednoc eb neht dluohs I taht
,srab paehc rieht ni dna
,retfa ylippah devil eh dnA
.naeco eht dleheb eh dna
.sevlesmeht dnif ot dehsiw yeht nehw
neppah ot sgniht eseht fo lla rof detiaw eh dna—
,retaw eht ni dessih dna
daed eht fo dnal eht hguorht deyenruoj eH
,evarb era uoy fi ,spahreP
,snialp ytpme eht ssorca rehtona eno ot gnilwoh meht draeh eh thgin llA .mih tfel dna
.emoh yenruoj eht nageb dna ,dnuora denrut
,erohsekal eht no nibac a dliub yam uoy ,hsiw uoy fI
,yrots a evah llits uoY“ ”?efil ym ton dna
.tols-liam eht hguorht repsihw dna rood-
.erif eht ta sdnah sih gnimraw ,nam eht dias ”,oN“
sesuoh dna serots—
”?dlrow eht fo dne tsomrettu eht ta
,sdneirf ym yb ,eid I nehw
,nrob neeb reven evah llew sa tsuj thgim eh taht hcus“
.nam eht deksa ”?woH“
,uoy evig lliw ti sgniht eht rof lufetarg tra uoht taht sees efil yht nehw ,nehT
.snool eht fo eno dias
.yaw eht tsol dah eh taht semit ynam deraef
,mih otni dehsur dniw eht dna ,did eH
sgnidliub erew ereht dnA
!reh evol dna ,reh dew
,traped yeht nehw
!thgif ot ro ,knird ot ro
,sevil nwo ruo evah eW
,thguac era hsif eht—
.erif no saw nosrep eht dna
.democlew tsal gnol ta dna
,pu doots nam ehT
daeh sih dellif dna
si efil A“ .dias dna
,no og tonnac yeht erehw ecalp a ot emoc evah ohw esoht era ynaM .no og lliw uoY“
,rewsna ton did legnA eht nehW
.mih erofeb reverof ti revo welb taht dniw eht dna ,naeco ytpme eht
,seveiht tuo peek ot ,serutcip ssalg eht revo srab erew ereht tuB
”,em morf depacse efil yM“
,tbuod on ,si siht dna
”!riaf ton si sihT
,enots fo tserof suotoir a ekil saw lardehtac ehT .od ot tahw
”,suoveirg si tahT“
”yawA naR efiL esohW naM ehT“   :yojne esaelP
.tesnus eht taht dnoyeb dna
.emosiraew ssel eb yam yenruoj ruoy taht
.edis rehto eht ot
.uoy ot nevig erew taht stfig eht was I tub ,drah eb lliw tI
,taob s’nosrep gninrub eht fo nrets eht otni debmilc nam eht oS
”,lla ta stiurf on erob efil s’nam a fi dnA“ ”.si tI“
.yraew saw eciov stI .dias legnA eht
,stserof eht ni dna snialp eht no
.saw eh lufitip woh tuoba
”,htaed fo sterces eht rof gnihton
”?yawa nar efil ruoy esuaceB“
won erew yeht os
,traeh tsomrenni yht ni neve
.em rof noitceffa yna desseforp reve yna evah ron
daed eht fo dnal eht nI
seye dna sepahs kcalb tub gnihton erew yeht taht os
”,dlrow eht fo srenroc lla ot tnatsni na ni levart I“
ereht saw dnal erom on dna
,dednepsus efil eht dna
.neris odanrot tnatsid a ekil eciov a ni
,yats ot daed eht fo dnal eht ot kcab enog ma I nehw ohw
,foor a emoceb dah yponac esohw
?uoy morf depacse sah efil ruoy fi serac ohW“
.yrots rehtona em llet
yam eh sa deeccus ro liaf enutrof sih ekam ot yrt ot
,tnemom a tub rof
!saw I gnorw woh ees nac I dna
,seirekoor dribkcalb eht morf dna
,skrap lanoitan hguorht meht dewollof eh dna
modsiW fo legnahcrA eht ksa ot
,tsoL era sevil dna ,tsol era
,srallip emoceb dah seert esohw
,etag nedrag sih ta gnidnats gnihtemos was nam eht
,yrots a rof kool tsum I“ .dias nam ehT
.su ot gnihton eb dluow ti
,ton od uoy fi ,tonnac uoy fI
dnim yht pu ekam uoht litnU
ti tlef nam eht emit eht yb dna
dnuos eht ssorca dewor nosrep gninrub eht sa
.efil ruoy si taht yrots taht
.klof-cro eht ot tnew nam ehT  .tfel eh dna
”?kees uoy ti si tahW“
,uoy gnillet si eh yrots a tub si ti taht wonk uoy fi tuB
”.em morf depacse sah ti rof ,efil ym gnikees ma I“ derewsna eH
dedulcnoc sah efil yhT
”.uoy yrrac lliw I
,yenom on evah I tub
,meht htiw knard eH
?wonk I dluohs woH“
.srao eht nwod nar semalf eht sa ,dias yeht
,tsehc eht no mih dehcuot nosrep gninruB eht dna
.gnillaf tuohtiw ria eht ni gnignah dna
”?uoy pleh ton ylimaf ruoy naC
.egap yrruFoS sih no sekoj dab fo tol a sa llew sa gnitirw sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,floWcaM boR yb ”yawA naR efiL esohW naM ehT“
”.depacse dah efil ym deciton I emit eht yb dessap ydaerla dah syad ym fo noon eht dna gninrom ehT
!thgil eht morf yawa ton nruT“
enoyna rof gnikees on si ereht
”.ti esu tsum ohw uoy si ti rof ,ti rebmemeR“
reverof nezorf era sdub esohw gnirps ni
”.erom yna fo draeh reven era dna
.denworf efil dlo ehT
,ereht si efil ruoy fi ton wonk I ,lleW“
.lufitud dna tnegilid neeb evah I“
.meht evol dna ,meht ekat
.delttes sevaw eht dna
,nam eht dias ”!lleweraF
,em rof ti evil I dna
rettam ton seod efiL
.seil ti erehw uoy llet nac I dna
mih ot dias tesnus eht dnA
meht fo lla rof emit eht dna
.kcab uoy deen ton od I .flesti rof ton
.nam eht dias ”,wonk ton od I“
eh dna ,reworran htap eht dna
,tesnus eht deknaht nam eht dnA
tnemamrif eht ot snoitadnuof eht morf
”.era yeht ohw wonk ton od I“ ”?noitan ruoY
.egrab maets a dnuora staobgut ekil
.emoh a yub ot hguone yap ton dluow ti
,stserof taerg was nam eht
”?eeht selbuort tahW“
?tfel ton dah ti fi
,dnah sti tuo dleh efil dlo siH
”?daed eht gnoma kees gnivil eht od tahW“
,evoba srats eht tub gnihton saw erehT
.emoh sih ta gnikool
,thgil eht morf tuo tsac dna
,gnis ew smeiuqer eht ot netsil dna
,gniveirG morf tseR uoy evig lliw I ,nac I elihw tuB
.gnihtyna niw reven dluow I
.tfel dah ti taht deraef nam eht taht hguone gnol rof tnelis saw legnA ehT .dias eh
”.evig ot enon evah uoy fi ,srewsna rehto
”?tsuj siht si woh dnA“
.ygrutil a saw ereht nehw evas
”.esoht fo enon evah I tub
”?krow ti seod woh nehT“
,tliub si tsen eht
.no tnew nam eht dnA
?uobirac eht gnisahc efil ruoy saW
”,rebmemer ton od I“
.htols fo ytliug tra uohT“ .legnA eht dias
.sevil rieht tuohtiw gnivil peek ot yaw a dnif tsol eht dna
,deedni teiuq yrev saw eciov s’nam eht
!esoprup tuohtiw tra uoht yhw
”?ylimaf sti fo egaruoc eht tub gnihton htiw dloc rettib eht dna
swonk ohW !gnihtyna
,evol ni llaf ot dehsiw eh—
.mih ekil hcum yrev dekool ti dna
”,siht ylno uoy evig nac I
,legnA eht derewsna ”,tbuod on evah I“
,sehsiw ym tsniaga
,tserof eht fo tuo emac eh tsal ta tuB
,neknus erew skeehc stI
,did I sa od nac uoy
,nialpmoc ton od dna
,srial dnuorgrednu rieht ni dna
.nees reve dah htrae no eye yna naht
,uoy was I tsal ecnis ,retteb hcum os enod evah uoY
,noitaripsni uoy nevig evah I“
”.ti dnif tonnac I dna ,erohs siht gnola lla thguos evah I tub
,erutnevda na no og ot
si yrots s’yadoT dna
evah ot rebmemeR“
”.og uoy rehtruf eht redrah sworg uoy erofeb yaw eht roF
”.kcab uoy tnaw I kniht ton od I tub ,yrros ma I
emit a nopu ecnO  floWcaM boR yb
”?tnaw I sgniht eht em evig ton seod ti fi od ot I ma tahw
”,uoy rof od nac I elttil si ereht nehT“
teef sih erofeb daerps shtap gnihcnarb dnasuoht dnasuoht a ekil
.syad sih fo dne eht ot
,og sevil erehw seiks eht morf nees evah eW
”,sevil hcus emos degduj evah I“
,dlrow gnivil eht ni ti thguos evah I“ .derewsna eh
,ti rof gnihton erac uoht taht
mih dlot scro eht dnA
,ogniD mailliW yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
.tfel sah ti os dna
,ylurt uoy llet lliw I dna“ ,dniw eht dias
,krow ym ekil ton od dna
”?em depacse sah efil ym yhw si
,etag eht ot tnew dna ,tuo emac eh oS
,no tnew nam eht gninrom eht nI
,ereh rekrad saw tserof ehT
,elbanigami roloc yreve ni
.semoceb ti tahw ro seog ti erehw ni yas on evah lliw uoY
.emoh sih otni kcab tnew dna denrut eH ”.eybdoog won
,deedni enog si efil ruoy fI
edis eht yb leenk ot dah nam eht
.namuh neve ton ecaf a won ,dlihc llams a won ,nam a won
.uoy nrecnoc dluohs taht htaeD si ti tuB
,tpew dna erohs eht no tas eh sa ,mih ot dias dniw eht dnA
,sliart emag nwod dna
,erohs rehto eht ot ssorc dluow uoy fi tub
semalf eht fo taeh eht morf yawa knurhs dna
”!elbissopmi si no gniog nehw no og ot woh em llet ,esaelP“
.thgin saw ti dna
mrots eci na ni eert a ekil
.sekal dloc eht fo sretaw llits eht no
,tsal ta derepsihw ti ”!noitidrep dna ysereh otni llaf ton oD“
.enog ylraen si nus eht ydaerlA“ ,tesnus eht dias
mih ot yas nac uoy
”?efil a hcus egduj uoy dluow woh
.esle gnihtyreve tegrof dna
,meht fo yraew werg nam eht dnA
?depacse sah efil ruoy fi rettam ti seod tahw“ dias yeht dnA
,lardehtac taerg eht ot ,ytic eht ot nwod tnew eh oS
,efil ni esoprup a evah
,ereh uoy evah ssenisub tahW ?nam gnivil
.esirnus eht kees ot erom neve yb etal oot dna
’,niaga tiurf raeb reven uoy yaM‘
.ti ekil yam uoy elttil revewoh ,dne eht ot netsil lliw uoy ,neht yhW
terger tonnac uoy neht rof
.erofeb tnialp siht draeh evah I“ ,tesnus eht dias
!thgilp ruoy ot dne on ees I
.pleh elttil uoy evig nac I tuB“ .tesnus eht dias
uoy htiw gnieb taht demees ti esuaceb“
,em pleh ton lliw sgniht nagapnu fI“
,em ot ylemoc demees taht namow a nees reven evah I dna
.ecnedivorP fo sgnikrow eht si ti taht“
.eno esoohc ot mih rof
.spahreP“ .dias tesnus eht
,scro htiw knird I
”?depacse efil ruoy nehw ,uoy erew erehW“
senots dlo fo lla edam
,mih ot dias yeht dna
did elpoep taht sgniht fo dnik eht erew eseht fo lla
.efil dlo sih deteerg dna
”!kcab ti teg I litnu meht wonk tonnac I dna
sruoy dah ew fi neve dna
,yawa depiw si htap taht
,deneppah ti nehw wonk ton od I .wonk ton od I“
,enog sah efil ruoy wonk uoY“
”!thgin eht fo tsom eht ekam os
.flesti retfa kool nac efiL—
yas tsum I meht ot dnA“
taht ees I od yad yrevE
,sgnilrats fo srumrum eht morf ti raeh I
.dnuor yaw rehto eht spahrep rO
,ogniD mailliW yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
.edis rehto eht no tserof eht hguorht dessorc nam ehT  .enog erew dna
.rotatceps esirnus eht
,erudne nac uoy naht nuf erom evaH
,egarohcna on dna
sgniht tnaw ot esaec ot mih ni ti dah eh kniht ton did eh dna
”?ecnedivorp emas eht yb tiurf fo kcal eht rof derehtiw
.sworb suoicipsus hguorht mih ta dekool ti dna
,seirots fo tliub si dlrow ehT
erac I“ ”.su tub wonk enon taht htaed fo sterces eht nrael lliw uoy emit ni dna
sseug ton dluoc eh esoprup esohw
,daed eht fo dlrow eht ni ti thguos evah I
.tsrif eht neeb sah emit hcae
,cisum duol rieht ot denetsil eh dna
.egaruoc evah uoy dna
tsew eht otni ssap sluos taht em rednu si ti
gnuoy eht ot neppah taht sgniht eht rof gnitiaw saw eH
,noon eht dnif nac uoy fI
,ytinav tsevarg ot esolc si fo kaeps uoht tahW“
.enog saw ti dezilaer I yad eno taht wonk ylno I
,evah nac uoy gniht a ton
,emoh a ekil dluow I esoppus I
”.nekops eman ym raeh ot esufer sretsis yM
thgin lla meht htiw pu deyats eh dna
,derised eh taht namow a nees reven dah eh rof
,sdeen nwo ym dna
,rehtohcae nopu delip seirots lla si ti
.sniatnuom naht regral seert htiw
”!rehtegot ylippah evil nac ew niatrec ma I
”?gnivil eht gnoma kees uoy od yhW“
,legnahcrA eht ot kaeps oT
,uoy erofeb stup efil taht sgniht eht lla ekil ot esoohc dna ,flesyht esuoR
,dnuos eht dessorc evah ew ,ereh tuB
,erom ekil thgim I krow rehto yna fo wonk I od ron
,nees eb ot niht oot tsomla
.ytinav sselesoprup smees dlrow eht lla llits teY
.suoitneicsnoc dna dnik neeb evah I
.gnivil eht fo sdnal eht ni ti dnif ton dluoc I
”.ylpeed ehtaerB .erom
”.lla ta wenk reven I eb yam tI“ .dias nam eht
,sdlohgnorts dnaletsaw rieht ni meht thguos eH
.riaffa ym fo enon si taht
,mih draeh legna eht tub
,yad eht fo gnidne eht ma I
”?depacse efil ruoy erofeb ,uoy erew ohW“
seviL .sgod fo gninihw eht ni dna
.dedaf ti sa derepsihw dniw eht ”.tnemom a rof
,sgniht eseht od ot liaf dluohs uoy fi neve dna
.hcus-dna-hcus eb ro
,eb ot desoppus saw efil sih revetahw dnA .tsap saw
.mih rof srewsna on dah scro eht rof ,no tnew dna
?kcap on uoy evaH
,dnas eht ssorca derrits dniw ehT
,yltneitap dehgis dniw eht ”?ton uoy od
”?kool ot ereht si esle erehW
.mih rof srewsna on dah yeht rof
,yletelpmoc meht derevoc semalf ehT
”,tluaf ruoy ees I kniht I“
,htaed rof tiaw dna nwod tis rehtie tsum eh dna ,yawa nur dah ti
eb dluow ti taht secalp eht ni kool yhw
”’.daetsni rehtona em llet ,eno siht ton ,oN‘
,sdneirf ym era yeht dna ,snool eht fo sgnos eht wonk I
”.sselehtenon no enog dna
,taob a ni nosrep a ot emac eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.yrots a si efil A
.enod neeb reve sah ti emit rehto yreve morf tnereffid ylrettu si ti
,denepo erew seye sih dna ,traeh sih dna
?efil ruoy tuoba snoitseuq htiw su elbuort uoy od yhW“
,stoor eht morf derehtiw era yeht dna
,yas uoy ,sihT“ dias eh dnA
.snier s’yrots ruoy ekat ylno tsum uoY ?yrots a
od lliw I tahw wonk ton od I dnA
nam eht ot dellac yehT
,dehctah era skcihc eht
”,ton wonk I“ ”?lla ta gnihtynA
,nis a si ti fo yna taht syas enoyna fi lla ta ton erac I dnA .em nruom lliw
ti fo niap gnitaicurcxe eht
,welb dnas eht dna
,su htiw hcuabed dna ,su htiw yatS
,mid erew seye sti dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rof erac I taht ,emoh a evah I .evol I mohw
,aes eht fo erohs eht gnolA
.ardnut eht ni pmac edam eh dna
,nwo ym no yawa tnew I oS
.thgis ni erehwyna
taht draeh dah eh rof
,em tsniaga srood rieht tuhs evah ylimaf ym tub
.tsap ydaerla saw
.ereht ton saw ti dna
.meht evah ton did eh esuaceb ylerem
,ylimaf a ekil dluow I esoppus I“ ,nam eht dias
,namow a won ,dlo won ,gnuoy
,doohtseirp yna ot llac yna leef eh did ron dna
,ni eb ot neppah uoy taht ti fo trap eht dna
?elpoep ruoy fo tahw
,gniht naw ,elap a saw tI
.rehtie ,em tfel uoy nehw riaf ton saw tI“
,sevlow eht dias ”.fo draeh reve
,suoremun erom dna suotoir erom dna rethgirb srats htiw
,trapa gnillaf dna ,meht edisni gnihton htiw—
.gnihtyna eveihca reven dluow I
.dlos dna thguob erew sgniht lufwalnu erehw setisbew rieht no dna
”,efil a evah I tuB“
mih ot neppah ot
yad lla dekcol saw rood eht dna
”yawA naR efiL esohW naM ehT“ saw sihT
,taob eht fo sedis eht revo dellips dna
lennut a ni niart a ekil tuo gnar eciov s’legnA ehT
.flesruoy rof evil ot yaw a dnif nac uoy
,emit dnoces a ti enod reve sah ydoboN
,efil sih morf detnaw eh taht lla wonk dna ees dluoc eh dna
.ereht ton saw ti dna
,sgniht fo nwod gnidniw eht
”?degduj eb llahs ew sevil ruo fo stiurf eht yb
.ssalg ni serutcip otni nezorf saw tiurf esohw dna
,noon eht kees ot em rof etal oot si tI“
”,esoprup a tuohtiw detaerc era enoN“ ”.enon evah I tey
,sredro yloh ot eeht gnirb ti rO
.efil a fo gnihton a em ekam dluow
?kcolf on uoy evaH
,sdneirf ro ,emoh a uoy gnirb ton seod efil ruoy fI
,uoy pleh tonnac ylimaf ruoy fI“
meht od lliw esle enoemos
dlrow eht fo elpoep eht lla
?og I nac sgniht nagap ot tub esle erehw
seiks erew ereht dnA
”.ton od I“ ”?dnatsrednu uoY
”.niaga efil ym dnif I litnu eno teg I nac ron
,efil ym fo sterces eht tnaw I“ ,nam eht dias
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.yaw taht krow ton seod efil A
,thgin swollof yad dna yad swollof thgin sa ylerus sa
,esirnus ta peels ot tnew yeht litnu
.elbmuh neeb evah I
,eno wen a tliub I os ,em tfel efil yM
,tiurf on sraeb efil ym taht ecnedivorp yb si ti fI“ ,naM eht dias
evah ew gniht tseddas eht si tahT“
,ecnad ot efil a deen t’nod uoy dna ,ereh llits er’uoY
.yrots rehtona eb tsum uoY
”.eromyna ,llew os rebmemer tonnac I
!kcab em ekat tsum uoY
,nam eht ot riafnu demees siht dnA
.gniveirg morf tser dnif dna
.mih morf yawa nur dah efil esohw ,nam a saw ereht
,dnabsuh a evah I“ .dias eh
?yrots a si ti taht wonk ton od uoy dna
,mih ediseb flesti derehtag dniw ehT .deksa eh
,uoy rof tseb si ,uoy evig ot sediced efil ruoy revetahw taht
,gnuoy regnol on saw eh taht dezilaer eh yad eht litnu
,mih dlot ti ”,yawa nar I“
”!sgniht nagap htiw sgnilaed on evaH
,aes a fo erohs eht ot emac eh litnu
setsat nwo ym ot ti tliub I dna
,daed eb lla yam ew worromot taht tub
,sevlow htiw rednaw I
,nwod tnew nus eht dna
xnyl dna sraeb ecaf ti diD
.niap on ni eb ot demees yehT
”.rehtie daed eht fo dnal eht ni ti dnif tonnac I fi
.won evah uoy naht erom on dnif dna
…tuB“ ”!nruter ti lliw
.uoy rof ti od nac taht esle gnihtyna ro
.rotatceps esirnus eht
ti dah I fi neve dna
,enod si ti emit hcaE
,dew ot namow a eeht gnirb efil ruoy nehW
.ti ekat ton did nam eht tub
,uoy selbuort tahW“
.demusnoc ton erew yeht tey
,dnal fo knab rehtona ees dluoc eh ti ssorca dna
.gniht nagap a ro
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,daed eht fo dnal eht ot yaw eht ot
,sevlow eht ot tnew nam ehT
,ssenkrad eht ni gninihs
.niaga ti gnidnif on si ereht neht
,kcab ma I won tub
,rood eht tsniaga desserp erew sgniw ynam stI .legna eht dias
,nwo ruoy fo efil a ekam uoy fi dna
.daed eht fo dnal eht ot deyenruoj nam eht oS ”!ereht keeS
,em morf depacse sah hcihw ,efil ym kees I“
,retal sraey ynaM
,aes eht ot yawa ylf uoy dna semoc retniw eht
?su ot efil ruoy si tahW
kees og lliw I“ dias naM eht
.nosrep gninrub eht deksa
,edit eht otni kcab taob rieht denrut yeht dnA ”.egaruoc
sniur egnarts dna skcolb tnemtrapa dna
.daed gnol eno sa em fo skaeps rehtorb yM
,ti od tsum ohw uoy si ti dnA
,yawa gnus dna ,desaeppa dna ,denruom eb tsum htaeD
,thgilnoom eht ni dnas etihw nopu doots eh dna
,emit fo dne eht litnu won morf kees dluoc uoy
,pihs on saw ereht dnA
.meht fo yna tuoba
.em tsniaga srood rieht tuhs evah rehtom ym dna rehtaf yM“ ,nam eht dias ”,oN“
?neht ,od ot I ma tahw ,lleW“
,htaenrednu ecaf rehtona delaever dna yawa denrub ecaf rieht rehtaR
”,os reffus ot tsrif eht ton era uoY“
.ksam gninihs a yb derevoc saw ecaf sti dna
.niaga ti dnif dna og ro
”-efil ym niager ot hsiw I fi oS“
eno uoy evig lliw I dnA
,ylimaf on evah I“
,deen uoy kcul eht lla uoy hsiw I
,hcus-dna-hcus evah lliw uoy taht ,uoy ot edam si taht esimorp a ton si efil A .evah ton ro
.seunitnoc yenruoj ruoy dna
,nis fo htap eht morf eeht peek oT
.yawa nwolb erew ti ni stnirptoof s’nam eht dna
,denruom dna derebmemer eb ot ekil dluow I esoppus I
’efil sih rof daed eht fo dnal eht tuohguorht thguos ohw nam eht‘ ton sI“
,flesruoy ot yas tsum uoy nehT-“ .dias eh
?enola llems yb retlehs dna retaw ot yaw sti dnif ti diD
”!dnim on meht yap neht