.tis ot meht fo rehtie rof tnemtrapa ynit eht ni ecalp ylno eht saw deb eht sa-
.won thgir uoy ot gnineppah saw tahw fo ,dnim ruoy ni
sgel sih neewteb no gniog
,tirips ym sgnirb ti rof
-senocenip htiw detnirp ,retrofmoc neerg eht ssorca rehtohcae deye yehT
,daeh sih revo trihs sih llup kalitreB tel eh ,snaej sih ffo dekcik eH
,enog dna gnidaf dna
.sih tsniaga sserp spil hguor tlef eh dna
,mih ot gnulc god eht elihw sdrow rof delbmuf kalitreB "...llew ,ko ,hU" !won thgir sserts fo tol a rednu saw eh tub ,yletaciled erom ti desarhp evah dluoc ebyam eH "!liat ym pu kcid emos dna
.tesnus eslaf remmus hgih
.ot txen gnittis saw eh ollidamra eht dias
,ylhguor ,kalitreB dessik niawaG
!erutan lla ot tnorffa na si sihT"
"?thgir ,rotsecna s'kalitreB er'uoy..." gniyas
,thgindim tsap llew sthgil ytic eht gnihctaw ,rehtegot deb taht ni eil dluow yehT
.dereffus evah tsum uoy woh"
.daeh sih koohs
?nam ,thgir lla ereht ni nignaH"
.rosivda sih ekil ylinnacnu dekool nam siht taht
renroc eht dednuor sub eht sa ,dessik yehT ".deb ym dnA
.deb eno eht dah ylno kalitreB
.ssalc fo yad tsrif
gnieelf saw ,rotsecna sih
.thgir sih ot dekool eH .saw eh reverehW
,moor citta elttil eht ni syad sti ecnis ,won dedaf erom
,ti ni gnihtyreve dna
niawaG ",yllautca ,si eh kniht t'nod I"
.deddon kalitreB "?dne eht ta
.lufetsatsid gnihtemos gniraeh fi sa
!uoy ecnuoned ot hturt ym ,sdrow ym
",tcepxe uoy naht retsaf
,mih raeh ...uoy dluoC"
,ylizal ecaf sih depmuh nosib ehT
,mih hguorht ,on
ssensuoethgir ym sa lanrete sa ma I"
.erew srehtaef sih roloc tahw ees ot tluciffid saw tI  ".od
,ytsenoh lufhsab fo lluf erew ,s'niawaG tem yeht nehw ,seye siH ".reverof
,oot railimaf yrev saw gnirutcel fo elyts sih dna
.tsal t'ndid ti tub
".noitpurretni eht fo erac ekat su tel dna
,wonk uoy ,elpuoc a sa meht rof sepoh hgih dah I
kcab htuom sih fo esu eht tog niawaG nehw os ,no gniog gnihtyna tuoba desirprus lla ta mees t'ndid eh dnA
",noitanimoba siht ,yticorta sihT"
...saw eh ,thgir s'tahT
dias wodniw eht yb flehs elttil eht no skoob eht fo tsoM ".taht
-ereh ni thgil eht tub ,tnecsediri yltnaillirb yeht erew ylno toN
ynohpocac eht revo tuohs ot ton thguof
,ssom fo teprac a no tlenk eH
.oot mih ekil deklat eH
.sruo er'uoy ,won sruoy er'eW
-dna ,dnah dereffo eht depsalc
niorg sih dnuof dah
...fo kcart peek nac ...I naht
.gnihton dias dna ,yawa ylhsipeehs dekool eH
',ot detcennoc' ,wonk uoy"
,selppa trat fo roloc eht saw tI ".drawkwa
.ssik a otni mih dellup dna
nrow a ekil ,tfos dna kciht saw no yal eh ssarg ehT
,enihcam gnihsaw eht ni kcuts gnitteg morf renroc eht ta deggar dna
,tsal ton seod ti fi neve taht si"
.mih ta deralg htob yehT
,eborhtab denetsafnu gnol a ylno erow toleco eht
,dekan ylluf yllacinhcet
.erom yna uoy esuba mih tel ot gniog ton
mih fo tnorf ni saw revetahw ta yldnilb debbarg eh ,kcab desserp eH
".dehsinif s'ti dna
,doolf gnihsur a tsniaga flesmih gnirohcna ekil
.noom egral ylbissopmi na rednu
,trevrep ,reverof uoy dnuoh lliw I dna
.sredluohs sih deldarc srehtaef kraD
kalitreB "?flesruoy mih htiw pu gnittup shtnom ynam WOH retfA !?yrros ER'UOY"
.senob sih ni ti leef dluoc eH .ecno ta noitcerid yreve morf ,staorht dnasuoht a ekil dednuos tahw morf ,mih ta yruf demaercs
.tsenrae ylgnihca dna wol dna teiuq saw eciov s'elkcarg ehT ".esimorp I
nesrow smaercs s'dahalaG draeh eH .ylirgna ,ylpeed
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT  .rehtohcae saw
.ssom eht sa erutxet emas eht ,roloc emas eht saw riah s'nosib ehT
...retsaf gniog s'ti tub"
.yrellaG yrefaoS sih no
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
dahalaG .tS hcihw ot
.roolf eht evael teef sih tlef eh dna mih dnuora ria eht ni dna sniev sih ni gniliob erew yeht ",uoy" ?mih edisnI
.skrow taht woh s'tahT .won ,oot rotsecna ruoy eb d'I gnikaeps yltcirts hguoht"
.yrtnuoc neerg raf a ni saw niawaG fo traP
",dal ,rehtafdnarg taerg taerG"
noitcelfer eht ni gniht ylno eht neht dnA
,shgiht sih neewteb kcab evod daeh s'nooccar eht erofeb "-
seog tI" .niaga mih depacse hceeps dna ,mih depolevne
.ruomarap tnerruc ruoy ,llew ,dna wehpen-taerg yM"
dettor sah ylurt ytiuqini ruoy neht ssendoog dna
,llih a saw ereht mih dniheB
",enigami nac I fi wonk t'nod I"
,sevaw naeco ekil dellor
,serguO'L fo dahalaG .tS
.htuom sih dellif ssik lufecrof dnoces a nehw ffo tuc saw niawaG "-
,tsehc sih tsniaga depporp god eht ta dennirg regdab eht
.snaej sih odnu ot nwod dna
"!krow annog si od ot tuoba er'uoy tahw deracs s'eh esuaceb s'ti yrgna s'eh fI !no dloh"
-erofeb ti evig ot teg t'ndid eh tnemmoc yna dah regdab eht fi os
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ti revo raeh t'ndluoc eH
,togib demahsanu dna ,rehposolihp ,naigoloeht
"!flesti efil tsniaga ecneloiv si sihT
.dnuohflow a was yeht
,flesruoy yojne uoy"
.mih ot deneppah reve dah taht gniht tsettoh eht neeb t'ndah ti fi
.delgnatne saw niawaG hcihw ni
.thgin eht ni tuo gninrub roetem a ekil
,niawaG drawot wap a tuo dleh toleco eht ",esruoc fo ,dedivorP"
skeehc s'god eht neewteb yaw sti dnuof dnah rehto sih elihw dluoc eh sa gnikorts dna gnisaet hcum sa ti evag
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
,dias eciov tfos a ",yeH"
,tfahs sih dnuora depparw erew spil s'enoemoS-
yletarucca erom ebyam ro ,flesmih ot ,dias niawaG ".did ti ...tI"
.thgir sih ot erehwemos ,eciov a dias
.devaeh tsehc siH
,hcuoc eht tsniaga mih sserp thgiew dekan s'regdab eht tel dna kcab yal eh
.redluohs sih revo dekool niawaG dna
.su fo lla wonk ot teg ot emit fo ytnelp evah ll'uoy ,yrrow t'noD"
.nus eht naht rethgirb dna neerg gninihs seye sih nees evah dluow eh flesmih ees ot elba neeb d'eh fi ",deeN"
,deunitnoc toleco ralucnuva eht
saw hgiht eht ni niawaG gnikop won noitcere eht dna
,dias evah t'ndluoc eh
,namahs ecivon a ,niawaG ,emit tsaL
.ylird ,dias toleco eht
,meht fo lla ,tneculsnart ,srevoc fo sreyal lareves edisa dehsurb dna
trihs sih rednu pu edils sdnah s'kalitreB tlef eh sa
,era uoY .ti yned t'noD"
,tuo dekool dna pu tog eh fi taht erus saw niawaG
,nooccar eht dehgual "?nuf gnivaH" .pit
er'eW" .ecaf dna sredluohs s'god eht dekorts srehtaef tfoS
"!evael dna pu evig I litnu pots annog s'eh kniht t'nod I"
.tsehc s'kalitreB ot gnignilc flesmih dnif ot seye sih denepo dna
dna ecitcarp dna yroeht tuoba gniklat
eseht piks nac uoy
detrats eh ,uoy edisni saw I sa nooS"
,tfahs s'niawaG depsarg
.evilo ot dlareme ot edaj morf sedahs tnereffid lla fo tliuq ocilac a no
...I" "?ko ,citnamor ylbirret eb annog t'nsi siht"
,ti leef dluoc eH
",sraey eerht rof ,talf rieht saw sihT"
sgel ym neewteb nam a gnitteg yllanif em fo aedi eht setah eh hcum woh tsuj s'taht kniht I"
.srae sih revo depmalc erew swap sih
,kalitreB ekil tol a dekool eH
.pots sub eht ot mih htiw deklaw kalitreB
,owt fo owt trap ,floWcaM boR yb
nibac eht tuohguorht egar ot deunitnoc nomres suoiruf s'dahalaG
,elbatrofmoc ylgnizama dekool
.rewop htiw gnimmuh ,dekan
,gnitser neeb dah daeh sih pal esohw ni elkcarg eht dias
.uoy rof nepo syawla s'rood yM" .dehgual kalitreB ".nossel
,rethgit gnulc eH
.deilper eh ",rehtob t'noD"
-bulc thgin a spahrep ,hcruhc a spahrep ,tluav fo dnik emos-
htuom s'niawaG revo dnah a dial elkcarg ehT ".retteb
,ereh enola erew eh fi sa ,yldeirruhnu
.ydob s'god eht gnirolpxe ylizal sdnah sih
,mih edisni sserp kcoc s'kalitreB tlef eh tnatsni eht krab eciov rehtona draeh niawaG
,elbaecalperri dna ,lufituaeb er'uoY
thgiN neerG ehT .yojne esaelP
.tS fo tsohg cibohpomoh eht htiw gnilaed pleh rof
"!pu tuhs mih gnikam tohs a ekat llew sa thgim I os..."
,ynoclab a ot ediw nepo nworht erew dne eno ta srood elbuod ehT
.retteb hcum os evresed uoy dna
.meht hguorht ni dehsaw dniw looc wols a dna
flesmih gnitcartxe trats ot erehw nwonk evah t'ndluow god ehT
"?neht ,ti fo gnivah er'uoy emit hguor a
tcaf eht morf tcartsid ot deliaf yletelpmoc dna
.smra s'kalitreB ni
,depmurg kalitreB ",dezama llits m'I" .dias naiwaG ",elpmis taht saw ti dezama llits m'I"
,ni erew uoy tnemom eritne eht fo erawa eb d'uoy yllautneve dna ,eno yb eno
,esoppus I ,tra eht ot hcaorppa
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
",dias I" -gnidulcni
,ecalp otni meht tif tsuj
,noitpecrep sih fo segde yrev eht ta
.htaerb rof gnitnap dna
,uoy tsniaga snrut yrecros larutannu dna luof ruoy woh ees tuB"
,drah oot gniggaw morf liat sih peek ot thguof niawaG ",lleW"
,syaw sih ni tes ssel ,regnuoy ,kalitreB enigami ylisae dluoc niawaG dna
.rae sih otni dias kalitreB
tuoba tnedifnoc ytterp saw eh
.gnirac ton flesmih dnuof eH
,denaom niawaG ",yeH"
.afos eht no kcab ,kalitreB ot depsag naiwaG
hturt fo rewop eht tsniaga
",pots t'nod ,kcuF"  "?uoy did
".taht fo erac ekat ll'eW
.mih dnuora erew smra s'enoemoS
s'kalitreB no kcab saw eh dnA-
-ti dessorc dah nus eht erehw dedaf elttil a-
lanoitar tsal yreve
.nrecnoc esnetni lla saw ecaf s'regdab ehT
,snoitcartsid eht nevE
,nayc yltniaf eht tsniaga deniltuo ytic railimaf a fo weiv a htiw ti detpurretni wodniw remrod elgnis a erehw evas
,tuhs erew seye siH
,leef ylmid won dluoc eh stsohg fo dworc eht ot
,ekal llits a saw mih fo tnorf ni dna
.kalitreB gnissim ylworran
"?reffo thgim I ecnatsissa dna htgnerts revetahw ,sselehtreveN"
.flesmih rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
.ti revo kniht ylerab dluoc eh
edistuo sklatsnroc gnuoy fo serca gnol ehT
-dnoces tilps a tsuj rof
,reiggahs ,redlO .emas eht etiuq ton tub
,ega nwo sih tuoba ,mussop A
tlobrednuht a ekil dahalaG tih
.sbewredips neeb evah llew sa thgim yeht taht hguone niht dna
,rotpurretnI eht neht dna
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
yrots s'yadot dna
,rehtruf elttil a tsuJ"
,larGeD lavicreP'
,dehcnuh erew sredluohs s'kalitreB
.regdab eht detnemmoc "!tihs yloH"
"?regdab a ...eb uoy t'ndluohs"
,ylteiuq dias niawaG "?tahw wonk uoY"
.neeb dah kalitreB naht rekciht
,niawaG dnuora smra sih htiw gniyl
,yrots eht ot gnihtyreve ddA .ssenerawa latoT
.pots eht rof dedaeh dna
".liame dedrow ylnrets a naht erom teg annog s'ycreP
,retrofmoc neerg railimaf a rednu thgin eht tneps niawaG
.drawkwa elttil a si siht taht"
,tuo dehcaer niawaG
.niawaG deddon ",haeY"
.tcejretni draeh d'eh eno emas ehT
.egartuo suoiruf htiw dednopser
.sdlohdnah ynit rof gnihcraes rebmilc kcor a ekil
.od uoy dna ,era uoy dna
S" .mih ta nirg ot sgel s'niawaG neewteb morf daeh sih gnisiar
.neerg flesti thgilnus eht denrut sduolcrednuht yvaeh daehrevo dna
,revir esiouqrut a otni ,taob a fo edis eht morf delgnad sgel riehT
.yllautca ,elbanosaer yltcefrep ...demees hcihw ,dekaN
"!enog s'eH !did tI"
steehs neerg reehs emas eht sgel sih dnuor dnuow dna sredluohs sih revo depard dah eh
.rettam t'ndid taht tub ,saw eh erehw dias evah t'ndluoc eH
gnihtyna ot tnuoma lliw nis nopu nis gnilip kniht uoy fi dnA" .mih eraperp ot
,ecivres ruoy ta ,trebhtuC"
,erofeb esicrexe siht enod dah niawaG tuB
.saw kalitreB reverehw
.rehtona eno rof dnif dluoc yeht noissap ssel eht rehtona eno detcepser yeht erom eht os dna
ti denepo eh dnoces eht
,afos eht otno despalloc eh dna enog saw ti nehT
,nwo sih htiw niawaG tcennoc ot xes evah yeht taht desoporp kalitreB .rotsecna sih ,dahallaG
.dias niawaG ",yrros os m'I ,tihs hO"
.nolhtaced xes fo dnik emos nur tsuj d'eh ekil tlef tI
,dekan osla saw eh dezilaer niawaG nehw saw hcihw ,pal sih otni pu niawaG dellup ,nwod dehcaer regdab rehto sihT
.noos revo eb annog s'thguord ,yrrow t'noD
,htuom sih fo tuo emac lla yeht
"?gniod er'uoy kniht uoy od"
.dog redle elbappotsnu ,elbacalpmi ,detnioppasid a ekil ,ylnrets
.dlareme peed fo sedahs ni dnuob erew meht fo tsoM
",eltneg eb ot emit tog ev'I fi wonk t'nod I"
,tuohtiw gnol ylriafnu enog dah eh esuaceb dna emit siht tnemyojne rof ylerup ,xes erom elttil a retfa ,gninrom eht nI
,floWcaM boR yb thginK neerG ehT
",kcuf eht tahW" "-rewop
.sepirts tnereffid
.taht ekil neppah nac tI
.moor citta na ni flesmih dnuof niawaG-
dnah tfos s'wollef siht esuaceb
.ereh morf ytisrevinu eht ees ot elba eb d'eh
,srotsecna evitroppus erom hcum
,won sdrow lautca ot kcab nettog yltnerappa dah dahalaG tS
.teef sih ot flesmih dellup eh sa
?eh t'nsaw ,xes gnivah saw eH .deknilb niawaG
peed dna tfos os
"!flesti taefed ot demood si od uoy gniht detsiwt yreve taht esle lla evoba sevorp siht yleruS
detaitas dna llits
,niaga kcab sih no gniyl saw eH
kalitreB "!noitaborper elbarcexe ruoy fo foorp si eergasid uoy tcaf eht dna doG erofeb nis a si sihT
evitisnes sih deniltuo eugnot a sa esirprus ni tuo deirc niawaG dna
,gnicniw eb ot demees eh dna
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,dnoces a rof ,tnatsid tnew seye s'kalitreB ".pots reve t'nod taht ekil elpoeP"
ohw ro ...ma I erehw
tuo teg ot deganam eh dna
!gnihton segnahc siht"
ro ecap eht pu dekcip dah kalitreB esuaceb rehtehw hguoht
,ehtaerb ot deganam niawaG ",erus-
,oot ,gnorts saw wollef sihT
degrof ecno dnob a
,ycapap dlo eht fo elcaro ,retpurretnI eht
.esoht ekil dekool taht seye ni tsol yrev gnimoceb
t'nsaw eH .seuh dlareme gnitfihs ylwols eltbus dnasuoht a saw-
gninetsil rof uoy knaht dnA
.reirgna dahalaG edam ylno taht hguoht neve
.noon saw ti ekil til saw mih dnuora htrae eht tub ,dellif-rats dna krad erew evoba seikS .saw ti emit tahw dias evah t'ndluoc eH
,daeh sih pota dnah eno ,redluohs sih revo gel eno dah mih revo gnimool nosib ehT
.deggag tsomla niawaG-  "-edir eht yojne tsuJ
,noitautcnup ni pitkcoc s'niawaG revo bmuht a nar eh ",kalitreB enildoolb rehto tsrif eht erew uoy kniht t'ndid uoY" .dehgual mussop ehT
".ti tpecca ot esoohc ew"
,mih htiw dias seciov rehto fo dworc elohw a "!PU TUHS oT"
,eno decneirepxe-hcum a ,kalitreB ot emac
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
.pmuts a no gnittis ,ereht regdab a saw erehT
.sdrow eht tuo ekam t'ndluoc niawaG tub gnivom saw htuom siH
,sehtolc lacirelc dlo ,ecaf nihT
saw tahw fo niaga erawa ylluf ylneddus ,dedda eh "...hhhooO !hO" ,depsag niawaG "!gnineppah s'tahw-"
,tsehc sih tsniaga deirub saw ecaf s'kalitreB .srae s'niawaG dnuora ohce dna
,tsehc suomrone na nwod gnikool saw dna
..." "...od uoy tahw rettam on uoy gnidnuoh peek annog s'eH"
ruf depirts hguorht sregnif nar eh
s'tI" .afos elbatrofmoc dna
".oot em otni gniyal
.htuom sih ni saw kcoc s'enoemoS
"...decivres gnitteg eno eht saw eh
,floWcaM boR yb thgiN neerG ehT
,raeh dluoc eh ylno wenk eh
kalitreB no dekcehc I tsal hguoht
,hguorht ekorb yllanif eciov s'kalitreB
"-erehw ssenkrad retuo eht otni tsac era uoy litnu
htgnerts fo ecruos a si
.sehsur dna seilil retaw fo lluf
",tra ruo tuoba rebmemer ot gniht eht tuB"
yrteop dna seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.detniauqca retteb teg ot snrut rieht gnitiaw
.lla retfa ,srotsecna nommoc tog ev'eW"
,drawrof mih llup dna ,ecaf sih fo sedis eht puc sdnah egral tlef niawaG neht tuB
,detuohs niawaG "!wonk I
,ylikeehc ,dekniw dna
,god.ecioVehT ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,derepsihw rotsecna eht ",dal ,ysaE"
,selppin sih fo eno htiw ysub saw eugnot s'regdab eht dna
.seerged rieht htiw od dluow yeht tahw
.gnippots fo ngis yna tuohtiw deunitnoc dahalaG .tS
ezeeuqs lufyalp a ti evag dna kcoc s'niawaG dnuora depparw dnah siH ".skrow
swaj lacisyhp lautca sih gnisu t'nsaw eh taht lufetarg ylsseldrow saw niawaG dna
,tlah a ot emac ti sa wodniw sub eht ni detcelfer ,tnatsni na roF ".lla
navid neklis naidiriv a morf ecaf sih desiar eH-
.sgel s'god eht neewteb srae s'nooccar eht dekorts
,daehrevo foor eht fo epols eht sa llaw a hcum os t'nsaw mih fo tnorf ni llaw ehT
.seye denethgirf ,spil thgit ruos
,llew sa mih edisni dna mih pota yal kalitreB dna ,dekaos ylleb ,afos
.meht ot pot yna ees t'ndluoc eh hgih os erew gniraelc eht revo gnirewot sdoowder ehT
,mih ta nwod dekool nosib ehT
?mih dniheb srehto leef dluoc eh ",kniht I"
,tnemom a ria eht ni gnah flesmih tlef niawaG
.saw kalitreB mih edisni peed woh dna
.ti otni yawflah naht erom knus seenk sih
.pots t'ndluoc eh tub pleh t'ndid tI
rieht ni tnereffid ooT
.ereht tsomla m'I"
",eerga nac ew kniht I"  .denaom niawaG "...ereht
,seert nednil htiw derevoc
gniyfirret neeb evah dluow tI .siht od ot
wonk t'nod I ,tahW"
,esolc mih dellup dna redluohs s'niawaG dnuora mra yrehtael a deppalc eH
...won thgir mih gnitnuom saw kalitreB ,noitom wols ni dna yawa yaw gnol a fi sa
.enips eht no 'DhS
".dekrow ti ,si gniht tnatropmI"
.t'ndid eH .detnaw d'eh fi
.dloh ti tel t'nod ,noitnetta ruoy barg ot deirt tahw rettam oN
.mih llik ot siht rof elbissop saw ti fi derednow eH
sdrow eht TLEF eh dna
.thguat gnitteg ton yltnerappa er'uoy sgniht eht lla ta"
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
.nossel lacitcarp rehtona deen I fi emoc ot erehw wonk I tsael ta"