,tnaem ti tahw wenk eh tub
.sdoow eht ni gnieb llits elihw
-?yawyna ,meht deef retnuh taht did tahw-
si yrots s’yadot dna
,rehtona ot hcnarb eno morf spael wef a
.lluf yltneinevnoc saw reddalb siH
.eromyna kcen sih dnuora epor a evah t'ndid eh dnuof eh nehw esirprus ni ffo ekorb neht dna-
,htuom sih ni deregnil llits kaets fo etsat eht ,lla retfA
-sdoow eht otni kcab daeh ot denrut eH
.mih ees meht tel dna tuo emac eh taht hguone tuo now ytisoiruc sih dna
.esirprus dengief nooccar ehT
.detpmorp nooccar eht "?ytterP" "...s'ehS
.ylleb nellows sih etadommocca dluow taht noitisop a dnif ot gniyrt
.knurt kciht s'eert eht pu dellac eH
,kao eht ot kcab deirruh nooccar ehT .lleW
?syad eseht doof god ni gnittup yeht erew tahW ".seno
,ylimaerd dias deR ",kaetS"
.sih htiw delgnim srehto fo tnecs eht dna
.selttob eht fo ylno dellems ti won tub ,did retsam eht sa
,ekomsdoow fo tib A
.pup a saw I nehw ecno ti daH"
-htaerb toh rieht llems dluoc eH  .esolc erew yehT
.gniklat retsaf emos dna gnikniht tsaf emos ekat ot gniog saw sihT
.uoy rof sehsiw ruoy ekam dluoc I ...esruoc fO"
,rennam deifingidnu tsom a ni liat revo eson gnilbmut mih gnidnes
,gol wolloh a fo retlehs eht ni netae
kaets enif a sa doog os detsat reve dah
degde eH  ".truh er'yeht fi etib thgim yehT"
,thgit tuhs llits seye rieht
.ton yhw ees t'noD" "?yllaeR"
",reve ,selttob on dnA" ".eno elttil A
.taorht sih deraelc eH
.retsam wen a tnaw eW"
,doog dellems dah ti ecnO
.dessarrabme dekool dnuoh dlo ehT ".hsiw
kcen sih no gnir eht tsniaga ezeerb tniaf eht tlef eh nehT  ...yeht erew tahW
.mih ta nwod dereep nooccar ehT
.ecnalg rehtona degnahcxe sdnuoh ehT ".did
.kcab eht fo tuo tpael yob A  "!daD"
-devirra retnuh eht ,retal etunim A
.t'nsaw--eno rehto ehT
.delrans deR .deR deksa ydduB
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.seno rehto eht rof
.deR ta dekool ydduB ".eurt
”eerT gnihsiW ehT“ saw sihT
-sdoow eht fo egde eht ta eert a ni deppots eH
.rehto hcae ta dekool
rennid eht ot thgir mih del eson sih ,edisni dna
,dedeen eh noitativni eht lla saw rood nepo tahT
.dloh barg ot gniyrt ,swap tnorf sih htiw krab eht ta gnilbbarcs ydaerla saw ydduB
,deR ,dnuoh redlo ehT
.ereht delian saw ,hserf dna thgirb ,ngis wolley A
.reve ,eromyna sretnuh on dna-
#   .emoh yaw eht lla
...os ,pu deit syawla er'ew tuB  .sey ,hO"
.retsam eht ekaw ot elba gnieb toN
.srae eht dniheb sehctarcs dna
.eromyna sretnuh oN
,dekaeuqs eh litnu denway eH
.detaeper eh ",ton yhW"
.ydduB ta dekool neht
,snoitacilbuP laoG morf
.tnaw uoy revetahW  .uoy rof eno dnA"
,yad taht wolloh yzoc a ni pu delruc saw eH
,erus rof sdnuoh ssel owt s'taht ,lleW
.dnoyeb sdoow eht dna
.won kcen sih dnuora epor on saw ereht tuB
ti bmilc ot evah uoy
.mih ta demia elfir nwo s'retsam sih ,ecnO
.seye sih gnisolc dna nroca eht gnihctulc
.roolf eht no od ot dah eh tahw did eh nehw tih neht dna
.su fo htob roF"  .deunitnoc ydduB ",eno tsuJ"
dleh nooccar ehT ".esnes naht tnecs erom htiw god wohs elttil a ton s'ti dnA  .efil ni tnatropmi yllaer s'tahw nrael ll'uoy yademos ,llew ,haeY" .dias ydduB ",doof si tuoba kniht uoy llA"
.yltfos dias nam eht
.elbat nehctik eht ta kcab decnalg eH
.swap sih no daeh sih dial deR ".retsam
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
!enim rof emit evah t'now ew ro" ,deppans deR
,dias nooccar eht ",erom on yaS"
"?won od ew od tahw oS" ".hpmH"
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,rennid s'retsam fo stibdit gnitteg derebmemer eH
.ton yhw ,yakO" .dedda deR
.lworg a htiw dias deR ",ti potS"
,etib ot tnaw mih edam taht niaP
.og uoy erehT"  .seye
.flesmih meht fo flah detnevni d'eh
.hguone llew gnihtaerb eb ot dekool llits eh tub
,ekil tlef ti tahw ees ot tsuj semit neves dnuora denrut
.emoh nur dna ,semit neves dnuora nrut ,seye ruoy esolc ot evah uoy ,sehsiw ruoy ekam ew retfa"
"?I t'nera ,god gnitnuh a m'I  .uoy dekcarT"
.dehcterts deR  ".os sseug I"
,gniltsur draeh nooccar ehT "?ton ro god gnitnuh a uoy erA  .diputs ,eson ruoy esU"  .seye sih dellor deR
"?tsrif eno elttil eht tuoba woH
,delbram dna knip peed
,llaH retraC eeneR yb
.detrats deR "...dnA" ".yojnE
,derepsihw eh ",srehcnip tuohtiw sdadwarC"
,delkcuhc nooccar ehT
,eugnot s'rehtom sih ekil mih revo gnihsaw
,delttes dna dehcterts deR
sdnuoh ehT ".nemeltneg ,gnineve dooG"
.mih ot txen gnidnats saw ydduB
,daor eht nwod dna llih eht nwod ffo ekat dnuohnooc kciteulb ezirp sih was retsam eht nehw dna
.pan gnol a morf pu nekow d'yeht nehw ,nwodnus retfa tsuj detrats dah tI
".eno doog a s'tahT"
tnecs ylio eht deirrac ezeerb gnitfihs eht dna
,secalp ni etihw yrevlis enog dah ruf nworb-yarg sih hguoht tub
,kcirt yreve wenk ylno ton eh dna
daehrevo gol eht ta deye-yraelb gnikool
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sdnuoh owt sih yb nwod delerrab tog ylraen dna-
,dias nooccar eht ",woN
”eerT gnihsiW ehT“:yojne esaelP
"?eert siht tuoba wonk t'nod uoy nehT"
".seert bmilc t'nac sgod swonk enoyrevE"
,tnemom a thguoht ydduB
.did eh fi niap esrow dna
,desolc seye 'sdnuoh eht sa noos sa dna ,dias eh "!enoD"
.eznorb nmutua sti ni desserd-ylwen
,ecno liat sih deggaw dna
"?ti si tahW  .thgir llA"
.hsiw eno dias uoY"
,wolley erew--deton nooccar eht--hteet siH
detrats semit dab eht
er'uoY" ".pup a saw I nehw eno dah I
kao llat a eb ot deneppah hcihw
llaH retraC eeneR yb
,hguorht dewehc t'nsaW
.hcnarb eht ffo llef ylraen dna ,yzzid tog
,yaw evig ot hcnarb nettor taht no gnitnuoc neeb t'ndah eh tuB
.daor eht ot nwod del ti dna
.yllanif deralced eh
,llaH retraC eeneR yb
,ksud otni delttes noonretfa sa gnizod
.seye sih desolc dna
,uoy knaht ot ,wonk uoY
.retsam wen a dnif dluoc eW"
"?hsiw rehtonA"
.daor eht nwod ydal a ...a s'ereht ,lleW"
:dniheb tfel dah retsam sih
.daor eht nwod god wohs taht fo dekeer ydduB dna
.knurt eht ta nwod dekool eH
teg dluoc eh sa yawa raf sa dna eert eht nwod flesmih deluah eh
drawretfa peelsa gnillaf sa doog os tlef reve dah gnihton dna
?...secnahc eht erew tahw tub
,rae tfel sih dniheb hcti na dehctarcs
”eerT gnihsiW ehT“
sih desolc nooccar ehT  ".ton
"?ereh si esle ohw-
ereh kcab-gnilbuod a
,sepor esoht gniytnu morf elttil a dehca llits swap tnorf siH
.eno elttil A  .no emoC"
,mih tuoba deklat sdoow eht ni enoyna nehw tub
.seciov rieht dezingocer eH
,ti deyojne ev'uoy epoh I
,dna yretslohpu nrow eht ot gel sih detfil eH
"!eno rof hsiw dluoc eW"
.yob doog a s'taht ,won ysaE"
.neerg dna gnuoy saw sdnuoh eht fo enO
eerf seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
"?ereh teg uoy d'woH"
,yawa ruf eht defahc dah epor eht erehw
flesruoy ekil eninac detacitsihpos a
langiS si koob tnecer tsom esohw rohtua noitcif ecneics dna ysatnaf a
,esruoc lausu sih tuoba tes dna
.ereh pu snroca fo ytnelp era erehT
",ti htiw tuO" "...atros s'tI"
,elttil a pu emac srae sih tub ,delbmurg deR
.gnirebmemer ,flesmih ot delkcuhc eH
"?reh dnif uoy diD"
.gnihtyreve detrats dah selttob ehT
.ekans daed a ekil trid eht ni yal tI
.sekarb fo hceercs eht draeh eh nehw decniw dna-
.yeH" .egduN    #   .mih dnuora gnignis sdoow thgin eht htiw
.ylimaf fo tnecs ehT
,nroca dnoces eht
.dias nooccar eht ",eurt s'taht ,seY"
,pu dewohs yeht ecnO
.spil sih gnikcil
,teef sih ffo dekconk neeb dah ,was eh ,ydduB
.nwod dna pu knurt eht dekool deR
.sdnuoh eht dewollof eh
,pup a naht erom ylerab kciteulb a saw ,ydduB ,eno regnuoy ehT
srrub htiw delrans saw taoc siH
-hteet sih ni ylmrif kaets eht dleh eH
.ffo deliart deR  "...rof hsiW"
.thgin doog a neeb dah tI
rood nibac eht tfel eh dnA
"?su ot gniklat eh sI"
.doog saw tI  .tnih a ton
.eye hcae ni dezalb eriflleh fo kraps a dna
htmraw s'erif eht gnileef
.rethgual depley ydduB
,devil d'eh sraey ynam woh fo tnuoc lla tsol d'eh taht semit ynam os egnahc sevael eht nees d'eH
.oot enog saw sih dezilaer eh
.ddo elttil a saw ti ...llitS
#    ".sseug I ,truh t'ndluoC  ...lleW"
,tuo emoc dah retsam eht ,etagitsevni ot elba neeb d'eh erofeb tuB
...a thguoht evah d'I
.nibac siht derebmemer eH .desuap neht dna
".eloh kcuhcdoow a morf ediskcab s'hctib a wonk t'ndluow uoY"
.enobder nrow-elttab a saw
.erom emos thguoht dna nwod tas neht ,liat sih desahc
".sretsam htiw enoD"
,od ot retteb gnihton dah dna suoiruc saw eh esuaceb tsuj
.oga gnol dah retsam dlo eht sa ,doog dellems eH
.gniyab sdnuoh eht draeh eh nehw
,esruoc fO"  .denialpxe nooccar eht ",tsom tnaw uoy revetahw uoy steg taht eert cigam A"
,ylmlac deilper nooccar eht ",lleW"
pu kcab dekool eH  .deppans deR ",uoy ,pu tuhS" .pu depip ydduB "?eert gnihsiw a s'tahW" ".eerT gnihsiW eht tuoba wenk sdoow eseht ni enoyreve thguoht I
,sracs deggar htiw dehcte dna
.gniggaw liat ,dias ydduB ",epoN"
dehctaw nooccar eht
,eert eht fo esab eht ot decar
.yawa evord navinim eht dna ,ni depmuj neht
,resolc kool ot daeh sih denrut deR nehw dnA  .tuc t'nsaw dna
,sdoow eht ni sdnuoh ssel owt rof edam ti fi tub
.retfa gnisahc tnew eh
.tnaem yeht ohw dootsrednu enoyreve
.niaga seye sih dellor deR "...os
,tnatsni na tsuj detatiseh deR
,flesmih dellac eh eno neve ton ,eman on dah eH
.emit siht kcab gnilbuod on eb d'ereht hguone raelc saw tI
".dnuorg eht tih uoy sa noos sa strap rednet eht gnitteg no gnirugif m'I dna ,yad lla doof nees t'nevah I esuaceb
.taem gnippird eht dnuora delworg eh dna
,pu tnew selkcah siH
.eert siht no wen gnihtemos saw erehT  .deppots dna-
eert eht fo tuo flesmih deluah eh oS
"?eno dnif ot desoppus ew era woh dnA"  .ti gniredisnoc
.deknilb nooccar ehT ".hsiw
.eerT gnihsiW eht s'tI" "?ti tuoba tahW"
.telliks nori-tsac eht otni deppals eb ot gnitiaw
,eert tseraen eht pu tlob ot emit hguone tsuj dah eh dna-
.did retsam eht sA
".ti ot pu era sruoy fo slian esoht kniht t'nod I dna
,llitS  .ssol ruoy s'taht esoppus I ,ylleb ruoy naht rehtraf ees t'nac uoy fi"
.moc.snoitciF suoiruC no
.derebmemer eh dna
,thgin lla ,yad lla edisni tuhs gnieB
,ti daer t'ndluoc eH
,rac eht morf teknalb a thguorb yob ehT
",yddub ,yeH" .eciwt neht
deeps-lluf gnipollag
.oot ,ecnahc sih ekat ot esnes hguone dah deR .nepo
.denraw nam eht ",kcab yatS"
".oga emit gnoL"  .dehgis eH  ".tnereffid
efil sih ni gnihtoN
.swap htob ni ylthgit nroca na dehctulc dna ,pu derebmalc
.ereh--morf--thgir owt hcaer nac I
.deksa deR "?dnegel tahW"
.hsiw rehtona ekam ot tnaw eW"
...gnihtemos detrats ev'uoy won ,lleW
"?syob ,niaga tnuh eht nO"
.nuf era seno elttil ehT
.thgin eht otni ffo dettort ,dehsinif nehw
,sehcnarb nekorb dna hsurbrednu delpmart eht lla htiw tahw
...llaf ot fael a koot ti emit eht ni pu eerT gnihsiW taht edam d'eH
.nroca na dekculp dna deggurhs nooccar ehT ".su
.tnereffid saw retsam eht nehw kcaB
,taews elttil a htiw niks namuh naelc
.kciuq sehsiw esoht ekam retteB"  .namuh fo
:ees dluoc eh sa raf sa
.yllufssilb dehgis dna
.tuo tog revird eht nehw delworg dna
.seimene sih fo wef a tsael ta tcepser ot gninrael tuohtiw sraey ynam os devil t'ndah eh dnA
,daor eht deredrob taht eert yreve ylraen no eno saw ereht dna
",pup a llits
,eert eht morF .dexaler neht
,seye s'nam eht gnihcraes ,pu dekool deR
-niaga gnilwoh kcisevol sih pu detrats dah ydduB
.liart sih dnuof sdnuoh eht sa tsuj
daeh eht no stap derebmemer
.edisni ylluferac dnuoh elttil eht deirrac yeht dna
.ereht thgie erugif a dna
,ekow deR ".yeH" .egduN ".yeH"
-seye sih desolc dna nroca rehtona debbarg eH
,rehtie ,selttob on dnA
.eert kao eht no hcrep sih morf hcaorppa sdnuoh owt eht dehctaw nooccar ehT
,gniyab t'nerew yehT
.hsulb eninac a ni daeh sih derewol ydduB  "...lleW"
.nooccar eht ta
.desahc reve dah dnuoh yna sa
"?eert gnihsiw a s'tahW"
"?uoy tuoba tahw woN  .yakO"
kcab sih otno dellor ydduB  ".sey ,hO"
,esolc emac nam eht sa denihw ydduB
.prahs llits erew yeht tub
.niaga meht denepo dna ,seye sih desolc
.hguone tsomla saw ti dnA
,gaw dna elggiw lla
,no hsiw ot ereh pu morf nroca na teg dna
mih revo doots deR
.GNITNUH ON  .DETSOP
:esora ytinutroppo eht sa stib ni gnidda
.retsim ,oot uoy ot gnineve doog dnA"
,sdoowkcab eht ni nooccar tsedlo eht saw eH
dnuorg eht ot nwod
.llac a edam dna enohp llec a tuo koot nam eht sa
nooc a rebmil dna yrps sa llits saw eh
,wollof ot ysae saw liart riehT
.ylfeirb seye sih desolc nooccar ehT .delwab dna
.htob ta retsam a saw eh ,yletanutroF
,renroc eht ni evotsdoow taht yb pu gnilruc derebmemer eH
,esuohgod detraehflah eht neht dnA
.eurt emoc t'now hsiw ruoy ro ,ereht teg uoy litnu seye ruoy nepo t'nac uoy dnA
.riahc s'retsam eht ta desuap eh
.nar dna semit neves dnuora denrut sdnuoh ehT
-su ot gniklat s'eh esruoc fO"
...ereh dneirf ruoy ta kool a tnaw tsuJ
,ecnahc sih ekat ot esnes hguone dah eh tub ,gnuoy saw ydduB
.thgit deit epor eht dna
,hsurbrednu eht hguorht tsrub sdnuoh eht ,retal tnatsni nA
"?ees t'nac ew fi emoh teg annog ew er'woh tuB"
-gnignis ti dellac eh-
.mih rof doog saw tahw wenk eh fi pu tuhs ot ydduB rof gnilley
.hcuot tpecxe gnihtyna wonk ot elttil oot saw eh nehw morf kcab
.spup gnilkcus erew seris 'sgod eseht ecnis deert neeb t'ndah eh ,nooM ydaL desselb eht yB  .deerT
.telliks eht ot txen thgir ,oot ,ereht saw selttob eht fo enO
,tuo yaw sih nO .dediced dna-
,maerts eht ni hsalps kciuq a
"!gnimoc s'retsam ehT
.hsurbrednu eht ni sevael daed pu derrits ti drah os deggaw liat s'ydduB ".uoy
,neht dnA .ti htrow saw ti
.navinim eulb-yvan a fo htap eht otni thgir nur dah ,desolc llits seye rieht ,sdnuoh ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.pu mih dezis deR .resolc
.did enoyna fi dnegel eht wonk dluow
.deppots reven dna
".lufrednow saw tI"
-eugnot sih no gniloop seciuj teews-tlas ylevol esoht-
.thguoht nooccar eht
,nur ot denrut ,ti debbarg eH
.tas dna pu dekcab dnuoh dlo ehT "...ereh
".kcab gniog ton m'I" .deksa ydduB
,kaets war suoegrog a
.enod llew boj a rof daeh eht no tap a neve teg ot regae