?tnemom a rof ylsuoires ti ekat
.sseug ot evah t’ndid I .sevlow erom owT
.hcnul gnitae neeb d’I erehw gniws eht morf enohp ym derehtag I sa em pots t’ndid ehs tub ,deworran seye ’sseB
,tih em dnuora ecaps fo noitcartnoc rehtona sa ,depsag I ”—ppah s’tahW ?ahW“
,sdoow ruo ni eert a kcurts dah gninthgil
dad ym—stnerap yM
.yaw ruo decnalg ti nehw
.netsil ot leviws srae ym edam taht lworg nwo reh fo enotrednu na htiw ,dias sseB
,devirra I nehw tops terces ruo ta ydaerla erew semaJ dna utS
.nrobbuts saw sseB
”…I ,oN“   .detrats I ”…I“
.tuo emac taht lla s’taht ,htuom ym denepo I nehw tub ,ti tuoba erutam erom hcum os eb ot tnaem d’I
hcnup laer a t’nsaw tI
.eromyna ton tsael ta—tsrif ym t’nsaw tI
.degnahc d’ehs fi su llet d’ehS“
.ruf saw ecalp sti ni dna
.egnarts saw ti tub ,eciov reh raeh dluoc I
tfel hcihW .semaJ yb yletades dewollof
tey tsuj ti nepo t’ndluoc I dna
!kool emoC !yeH“
elacs a saw dias moM taht ygniht-ylgnad dreiw a—
utS fo seidob nellaf eht otni pilc eritne s’nug fren reh gniytpme ,em denioj ehs sa yrc elttab a tuo tel dna
.ytefas ot eelf ot elba saw ti erofeb gel eht no etib
,niaga ruf nedlog eht ot kcab saw tI
,ydaets ylgniteiuqsid erew taht seye eulb gnicreip dah ehS
.dE ,uoy dessim eW
.galf eht em werht neht ,decnuonorp sseB
deddon I   .kcuts dah eman eht dna ,dehgual dah moM
”?rebmemer ,eromyna kcap eht fo trap toN“
niaga delwocs sseB
.em thguac ehs dna delbmuts I
?krow neve taht seod woH ?daeh ym fo pot no denrut srae ym ,tiaW
.revo saw emag ehT
.hcaorppa ym draeh evah dluow kcaP eht taht wenk I os
etal oot—dezilaer I nehw raef fo hsur dloc emas eht tlef I
.sregnif ynniks ym ot kcab knurhs tsrif ym nehT .nedlog dna kraD
ym rof em emalb t’nod ,no emoC
.yllufthguoht pu depip semaJ ”.rettam t’nseoD“
,sneilA susrev nemowecapS gniyalp neeb d’ew tub
.sdnoces wef yreve gnitrotnoc ecaf sih ees dluoc I tub
.ti morf sretnilps gnitteg deppots ecnis gnol d’ew taht gnibmilc tnatsnoc ruo yb nrow os
naelc htiw tub sedis rieht pu gniworg ssom htiw
.redluohs eht ot hcnup ciots erom hcum ’semaJ yb dewollof ,mih degguh dna
.delims yllanif sseB ,ezag reh gnikaerb tuohtiW
.em rof eman sih saw tahT .deksa daD
.yawa nur dluoc ti os esuoh eht fo tuo teg ot hguone tsuj—ereht walc a dna ereh pin a ,su truh tsuj d’tI
.ecalp terces ruo fo kcab eht ni dehcnup dah ydob ’sseB eloh eht ta derats I retal tnemom A
”.emoh og attog I“
.dael reh gnikat erew yehT .em dna
.pirg rieht tsol esle enoemos litnu rehto hcae dnuora sgel rieht parw ot deirt dna
.llems dluoc I tahw ot yradnoces tsuj saw ti tub ,ees dluoc I
?kcab teg uoy d’nehW“
”?neht ,kcab emoclew a tnaw uoy sseug I“   .deksa I ”?sseB“
.detuohs dna ,daeh ym revo ti desiar ,ti debbarg I
.kcaP eht otni kcab em tpecca ot meht teg ot—
.deracs eb dna yad taht ot kcab hsalf d’I taht yracs os saw cipot lareneg eht tsuj fi sa
”.kcap eht tfel ehs erofeB“
.ffo raf ton tip dnas eht morf laeuqs s’utS draeh I
.racs ym ot noitnetta ward ot ton dluoc eh gnihtyreve did daD
,yadretsey morf regna taht fo hsalf a tlef I   ”.dE yrroS .t’naC“
.diasnu tnew gnihtyreve ,nwod kcab dluow su fo rehtien esuaceb tub ,yrros saw ehs dna
ni neeb d’eh eert eht fo tuo llef dna
a mih thguac flow eht tub
.tsif ym ta nwod dekool neht
.edis eht dnuora sseB dewollof dna dnuora denrut I
,dnuorg eht otno dleh I emit sihT
,tnavresbo ylralucitrap t’nsaw eH .ni dereep utS
.mih no dednal flow eht nehw
.truh d’ti tub ,htiw rehto hcae tih loohcs ni syob eht fo emos nees d’I ekil ton—
…syug uoy won dna ,pu gnikaerb si ylimaf yM
,ecaf sih ni truh eht was I
d’yeht wenk daD dna moM sa raf sa esuaceb ,flow a rof deraperp neeb reven d’ew tuB
”.gorf a dewollaws uoy ekil kool uoY“
.ereh yats ot tnaw t’ndid I
.niaga gnitruh saw racs ym dna gninrom eht ni ekow I
,teknalb erutainim a otni ti nwos dah mom sih os
.drah ti tuhs dna rood eht denepo I
.rood eht ni kcarc eht ot eye ym tup I ,gnitpurretni fo daetsni dna ,pmurf deifitsuj ym hguorht tuc tI
.diarfa eb ot hguone llew wenk su fo enoN
”.og ot detnaw ehs ekil ton s’ti ,yawyna dnA .taht dias uoy ylnO“
.ti debbur I nehw yawa og t’ndid ti emit sihT
.sseB tsniaga syob owt eht emit siht
”.yawyna tnew ehs tuB“
.thgilnus erom ni gnittel ,esuoh eht otni llef tsuj ti
,rekrad elttil a dna delttom dekool tsuj racs eht os niks thgil htiw su fo eerht rehto eht ekilnU
.sseB saw ti kniht I ,tsael tA
,kao dlo eht ni syeknoM deyalp eW
.ralloc a ees t’nod I .wonk t’nod I
.llew yawa gnivom saw I taht swen eht nekat t’ndah ehS
.efas ton s’tI .t’nsah ehs dnA
”.yrroS“   ”!ecaf eht ni toN“
.neeb dah syawlA
,saw I das woh wenk em dnuora enoyreve taht erus gnikam si
emoceb d’ew ecnis toN
meht htiw og ot edam d’I noisiced eht saw lla ti revo gnignaH
utS htiw yllaicepse ,yrros saw I yas ot woh wonk t’ndid I tub
.taes sih morf yltnelis gnivresbo saw semaJ dna ,yawa snug eht tup dah utS ,tniop siht yB
.gnizzub saw enohp ym dna
neeb lla d’ew ecnis ,eno dah kcaP eht ni su fo ruof llA
.yrolg enipul reh fo lla ni
,hU“ .hguorht dellup esnes nommoc sih emit siht tub ,sessalg sih htiw neve
,detsixe sgod yarts taht wenk lla eW
.tew teg t’ndluow ttub ym os tuo nur wed s’thgin tsal fo lla tel ot tuo ti
-   .hteet wolley dna seye wolleY   ”.tiS“
—nehw llew os taeh s’yad eht dleh taht
.reh was dna denrut I
.utS saw eno dnolb-thgil eht dna ,semaJ saw eno der-nrubua eht taht em dlot eson yM
.kcab ym fo ffo ecnuob sehcnarb eert ybraen dna
.desaec seitilitsoh fo tser eht ,dellac neeb dah emiT renniD tsomlA fo ecurt eht nehw tub
esuoh eht ni dewolla saw detaler-god gnihtoN .sgod yna evah t’ndid tI
.edis eht ot ffo detuohs utS nehT
deppit I .riahc ym devom t’ndah yeht ,hguoht ,em ta gninworf saw sseB sa hcuM
.sessalg sih tih strad maof reh fo eno nehw denialpmoc remrof ehT .semaJ dna
.keehc ym no saw eniM
.dnoces a neht ,su delcricne smra fo riap rehtonA
.egnarts os saw tI
.sredluohs reh no kcalb-raen thgilnus-eht-ni-laoc a ot
senots eht no setunim wef a rof gnitser tsuj erew ew os—emoh nur ot derit oot neeb d’ew dna
.eert a thguac dna tuo dehcaer I
.ereht deyalp ew taht wenk daD kniht t’nod I
.oot ,llaw a hguorht dehcnup neeb d’I fi egnarts dnuos dluow eciov ym teb I ,niaga nehT
”?noonretfa siht su hctaC“
,wor a ni pu denil lla skcor eht rebmemer tsuj I
.daeh ym ni deifitsuj I os ro—
.tsaot dna gge ym dehsinif dna deddon I
,nehw-swonk-ohw ni kcab tliub saw taht
.ezigolopa ot reh rof gnitiaw
.ecalp terces ruo saw knurt dlo sti fo mir tuo-dewolloh won eht nI .swen lacol edam yllautca dah gnillaf sti dna ,eert evissam a neeb d’tI
.ezingocer ot elpoep rof hcum oot saw taht neve taht demees ti tub
,etalp eht sa talf sa tsomla saw ,rehtegot tup lla nehw ,taht tnuoc ot stneidergni ynam oot htiw hciwdnas driew a(
.esuoh ’semaJ ot yaw trohs eht koot reven eW
.esuoh eht otni ees ylerab ylno dluoc ew ,utS ot ti edam ew nehW
hcnarb eht no dloh sih tsol tub neila na ekil raor ot deirt dah semaJ nehw emit taht tuoba gnihgual llits erew utS dna sseB taht nuf os neeb dah semag eht ,yawynA
.yeknoM gniK eht saw ehs esuaceb ,reh htiw deerga lla ew dna ,oot slrig eb dluoc sgniK taht deralced ehs
.noonretfa siht rof niw eht em gnidec
.did I   .detnuat sseB
.thgir saw ehS .deddon I
.edis ym ta saw enoemoS
,yrc ot detrats dah sseB
.racs s’utS .racs a was I ti hguorht dna
”kcaP ehT“     :yojne esaelP
.retfa setunim wef a ylno saw sseB dna
.em dnuora nups dlrow eht sa hcamots ym fo hcnelc a tlef I dna
.ecalp terces ruo neeb dah taht knurt eert eht fo sniamer eht naht neve rellat saw ehs gnidnats taht llat os—llat saw ehS
.sselwalf saw hsubma yM
taht ediw os elims yddig a htiw taes sih ni dnuora denrut saw utS
?yrgna llits ehs saW
.tsol neht ,dednefed neeb dah tiP ehT
,redluohs ym no daeh sih dial eH
,etal gnieb rof elbuort elttil a otni teg d’I wenk I
.ediced ot struoc eht rof saw ti dias daD
draeh I nehw ,nepo ti hsup ot tuoba saw I
.erehwyreve desiurb saw I ekil tlef ti dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”!sruoy si tiP dnaS ehT“
.em dnuora tnelis saw enoyrevE
.lirep elbirret ni erew su fo lla taht—
,elbirroh gnieb saw ehs nehw tpecxe ,moM did rehtieN
tsafkaerb dehsinif I emit eht yB
.ti no nrocinu a fo erutcip a htiw trihs-t dlo na saw tI
.ti tuoba demaerd tsuj dah I ,niaga nehT
,hguoht ,hsubma ot evreser ni em tuohtiW
esuoh eht fo sniur eht hguorht detarebrever ti taht ssab fo lluf os—lworg a draeh I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
uoy dna ,niaga kcap elttil nwo sih morf guh a teg nac eh os revo eb ot enitnarauq rof regae si ohw
.em ot txen gnippay llits
,neeb dah ti ereht tuB
).ecuas yrovas dna eseehc htiw
,rehto hcae ot elihw a ni ecno ffo meht dewohs eW
.snaeb eht ni thgir mih tih I dias tsuj eh
,ruf eht ni hctap knalb a was I ,tsirw eno nO
.thgil gnineve eht ni mid
”.elohssA .ti rof em thgiF
.ti od oS“   .deddon I oS
.tlep nedlog emas eht dah ti ot dehcatta mra eht emit siht dna
”—erofeb ,raey tsal ekil tsuj eb ll’tI
.pmiw ,no emoC .em tiH
.reh hcnup ot detnaw yllaer I
”.ot tnaw t’ndid I wonk uoY
knurt eert dettor dlo ehT
.riahc nwo sih ot kcab utS gnigdolsid ,tas I
.enob keehc ym revo senil elttil ynniks evif—
.oot ,gnilims saw eh taht llet dluoc I dna
.htuom ym ot kcuts ti hguoht
,sriahc citsalp owt htiw
,ekil dekool ti tahw dias d’I nehW
,seert eht fo spit eht ssorca gnilwarc noom a dna
.elbazingocer naht suortsnom erom kool ot edam ,swaj gnirevals dna hteet evissam
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,lerdnaK yb
.sseB revo yltcerid depmuj dah tI
,oot ,mih fo tuo dekconk htaerb eht dah d’eH
,kcab reh no dednal ti dna ,derewoc ehS
.sngis eht ezingocer t’ndid I os ,step dah reven d’I
,reh dehctaw yehT
.rehtegot tup su fo owt yna naht reggib saw ti hguoht neve ,su fo deifirret saw ti taht won wonk I
,ereht deyats yltsom ew sa gnol sa
,niaga delworg god ehT
.sseB no erew seye yM
,detcejeD   ”?yako ,worromoT“
.ycnegreme na saw ti sselnu erew ew erehw wenk yeht ekil tca dna tuo emoc t’ndluow yltsom stnerap ruo
,eno derenroc dna deracs a yllaicepse ,flow a taht tcaf eht rof em deraperp dah meht fo enoN
,’nonnac ehT‘ gnimialc dna
.em tih ehs ,kcab eb d’I reh llet ot deirt I nehw tub
”.tsael ta ,remmus eht rof kcab m’I
,desrup erew spil reH
.htuom sih revo erew sdnah sih dna ,edis eht ot su dnuora emac utS
,feilebsid ni derats I
.thgin tsal ffo em deppord moM“
”?yako ,mih llac ll’ew dna wonk em tel
.elbarapesni erew su fo ruof eht dna
.gnorw saw ehs wenk I tub—truh dah racs ym naht erom neve—truh tahT
.ecaf sih fo tnorf ni pu dleh saw ti erehw mra s’utS neht dna
.niaga depael ti sa redluohs reh gniwalc
,no dnuow emit sa zzub ot detrats dah hcamots ym ni seilfrettub ehT
.deggurhs eh ,tsafkaerb dehsur ruo ta daD ot pu ti thguorb I nehW
”!hgrrrrR …tsuj I …si kcaP yM
.desiurb tlef I dna
,gnorw saw gnihtemos llet dluoc eh kniht I
yrotsih s’dlrow elohw eht ekil s’tI
.snac dna sexob dekcap-erp ni emac dedeen eh gnihtyreve dna ysae saw ti esuaceb ebyam ,kooc ot etirovaf sih fo eno saw tI
,detterger yllaer I taht tfel I erofeb dias neeb dah sgniht emoS
,sraet neewteb em ta deralg d’ehs dnA
”?kcaP eht ot kcab gniog eW !zzuB“
llaw trof reh revo detluav sseB
.yaw gnol eht koot ew elihw
.galf ruo emoceb dah teknalb taht dna
.daeh reh koohs ehS   .detrats I ”—I tuB“
.dias I ”.tsol skool eh ,wwA“
.dlot neeb d’ew ,ykcul erew eW
seye reh ni erif emas eht was I dna
.tis ot dekil sseB erehw dnuorg fo wolloh naelc a dna
.ereh ni esolc oot saw gnihtyrevE
.kcab delwocs I ”.ecin eb d’tI“
,drahcro eht raen sdaorssorc liart dlo eht tsap su nekat evah dluow tahT
.tsirw sih no saw s’utS
,reh ta derats d’I .taht
,ytsat erew slezterp taht dias ehs tub ,ti naem t’ndid I taht sseB dlot d’I
.racs tseb eht dah ylraelc ehs os
,niks krad reh naht rethgil saw ’sseB
.em morf yawa dehsur dnuorg eht dna ,nwod dekool I
.yrc tnerehocni na sa tuo emac tsal ehT
,deppord ezag reh nehT
…erew ohw daD dna moM ekil toN .yltsom—
.devirra I emit eht yb htaerb fo tuo saw I   .emoh nar neht
ereht tog I nehw tub
.enola em dna sseB
.dE ,og uoy ereht ,haohW“
.elbirroh tlef I ekow I nehW   .devol saw I
,edur yllaer gnihtemos gniyas fo daetsni os
.reh tih I neht dnA
,kcab derats I dna
.su ot meht nevig d’tahw ot kcab kniht ot detnaw yllaer su fo enon
.rood neercs eht fo eldnah eht no llits dnah ,pil ym tib I
.eciohc reh t’nsaw ti ekil
ti no lobmys eht dezingocer I
”.t’ndiD“   ”—htiw emoc nac I syas eH
.god a ekil tsuj kool dluow
,moor ym ot denruter I
”.uoy tih I yrros m’I“
sti gnola kcab dennip erew yeht hguoht
.knilb a ni deraeppasid noonretfa ehT
.em htiw ereht saw kcaP eht dna ,mraw saw I tub
.eloh-yedih elttil ruo otni yaw ym dekcud I sa nedrub a gnimoceb
.daetsni kaeuqs a tuo tel dna
.kcarc a tub lla ot desolc rood eht htiw
,enohp sih dekcehc semaJ nehT
,sseB ta tespu llits saw I
.terces a yletelpmoc t’nsaw ti sseug I
.saw ti sdaeH .ti deppilf dna
kcuts saw rood eht dnuof I ecnatsid eht ni eman ym draeh I nehw tub—ni netsil ot naem t’ndid I
noisserped yratilos detcilfni-fles ym etadilav dluow taht gniht ylno ehT .debbor tlef I
,riahc a sa desu eh pmuts eht no em morf yawa denrut llits saw ydob ’semaJ
,gnihctaw saw moM
,em fo tnorf ni doots ehS
.ruf fo hsalf rehtona was dna ,edisni morf enihw a draeh I
,deggurhs sseB ”.ylno kcaP .t’nac uoY“
.evael ot tnaw t’ndid I tuB“
nehW“ .kaeps mih tel ot pu tuhs sseB neve dna ,denipo semaJ
.niw reh tel ot gniog t’nsaw I tub
yrgna gnieb dna—emoh kcab gnieb ebyaM .emit gnol a rof tI
.ezigolopa t’ndid tub
,niks thgil ym saw enoG
.deppirts gniriw sti fo lla htiw noitatsbus cirtcele desusid a—
.yawa dekool neht ,delbmuts ehS
gnineve eht ni xiS
.selur eht eb yalp ot dah I tub
.sreh ni dnah ym thguac ehs dna ,tuo dehcaer I
,seirots ym fo eno em daer d’eh fi dad deksa I
hcnarb tsewol eht morf gnuh eerht rehto eht elihw stoor delrang eht ni tas I os
,yrc ot ton tseb sih gniod saw daD
racs ym fo senil lacitrev eht decart ti nehT .ruF
.reh htiw teef ym ot em dellup dna doots sseB ”.haeY“
,eb d’yeht erehw wenk I
ria eht ni gnilialf dna
gniyalp peek ot derit oot lla erew ew erofeb ,elihw a rof sruasoniD gniyalp otni denrut tI .reh dettubdaeh dah utS nehT .em tih d’ehs
.redluohs ym no llams tlef dnah siH
.rettel a ekil dedlof-irt—
.tsetaen eht saw sreh thguoht I dna
”?snaeB ,yako gnihtyrevE“
skcab ruo no edir reh gnittel snrut koot eW
,draeh gnieb tuohtiw ecalp terces ruo ot teg t’ndluoc uoY
.uoy tuohtiw dekcus loohcS
.hctorc eht ni mih tih dah worht tsrif yrev ym ,llabtfos a worht ot woh em hcaet ot deirt tsrif d’eh nehW
,niaga ’em‘ saw I nehT
.gnihtemos dias eh nehw netsil ot dednet lla ew os ,hcum klat t’ndid eH
tops terces eht ot kcab pirt kciuq A
,thgin ta dloc saw tI
.saw yllamron eh ekil tuo denoz saw semaJ
.rehtie ,eromyna sraet fo dioved t’nerew seye reH
,yeknoM gniK denworc neeb dah sseB nehW
.oga sraey ti nworgtuo d’eh tub ,s’utS neeb d’tI
.dias I ”?eeS“   .deddon eH
,sih sa demialc semaJ taht pmuts gniniamer eht fo tib a
.maerd gnitrofmoc a saw tI .maerd railimaf a saw tI
.oot ,ffo saw eciov sih tub
”?yarts a s’eh ebyaM
,yletarucca erom ,swaj sti ,lleW
.elims gnilkniwt a ees dluoc I dna
.emoh eb ot dah I erofeb tfel ruoh na ylno dah I tnaem taht
a otni ekorb ecaf ’semaJ nehT
.deil dah serutcip eht lla tub ,dooH gnidiR deR dna sgiP elttiL eerhT eht ekil ,skoob erutcip nees dna selat yriaf daer d’I
,detanimulli ylluf woN
.niks ym morf yawa sraet dehsurb bmuht reh fo dap yrehtael ehT
,yks eht ni hgih saw nus eht
sehcnarb rewol sti htiw
.redluohs reh fo kcab eht no lezterp a ekil dekool os
,ksud ta senots eht fo htmraw eht nI
,yduts sih ni mih dnuof I
.evila tlef I .delf tsuj sehca elcsum elttil esoht lla dna ,gninrom eht ni gniht tsrif dehcterts d’I fi sa saw ti dna ,doots I nehT .denway dnA
.tlep ym fo sreyal eht htaeneb ereht eb llits tsum enim—
.tuo detrulb I ”.syug uoy htiw emoc ot tnaw I“   .detnemmoc sseB
.won srebmit dettor-yldab fo llehs ytpme na naht erom ylerab saw dna
,setunim evif nihtiW
.htworgrednu tserof eht otni tuo deppets eW
.eguh saw ti esuaceb niaga rof kool og ot dah ew taht revir eht raen nwod dnuof eh gorf a
.edis rehto eht morf doow eht no swalc fo elbbarcs eht draeh I ,dessap I sA
,reywal ecrovid s’mom yM
.yrgna dna toh tlef I
?yako gniod uoy erA
.keehc ym dessik neht ,ecaf ym otni delims ehS
,erew ew ereht dna
,ylruos deilper I ”.od ot sgniht kcaP terces
.em fo daeha kcaP eht htiw yad elohw a dah I dna
”!ti nrae uoy fi ’kcab emocleW‘ ruoy teg uoy ,yakO“
.retfa dewollof semaJ dna
,elgna egnarts a ta yawrood eht hguorht gninihs saw thgilnus ksud eht fo tsal ehT
.oot ,em ot terces a saw ecalp terces eht ,won thgir dna ,dewollof eb ot dah selur neht ,gnihtyna tnaem yeht fI
!gnihtemos rof tnuoc ot sah tahT .ot tnaw t’ndid I“
.stlob maof eerht dah ylno taht
.sraey rof ti leef d’uoy dias rotcod ehT“
.retsnom driew emos saw I fi sa ,em ta gnirats lla erew yehT
.em morf yawa tohs ti sa sregnif ym neewteb sevael
.hteet esoht lla fo esuaceb
.lamron s’taht kniht I tub ,ecin leef t’nseod ti wonk I
.gnitruh deppots d’ti ,yawa tsirw ym
”.haohW“   ”?siht ekil gnieb htob uoy era yhW“
keerc elttil eht tsap tuo
.fo tros ,tluaf ruo neeb dah tI
dellup I emit eht yb dna ,dnah ym fo kcab eht htiw ti debbur I
,god a dah reve dah su fo ruof eht fo enon
.tnew secarb sih kcab raf woh ees dluoc I
.telliks toh a no retaw ekil yromem eht ffo detaks dnim yM
”.ti naem t’ndid I dias I“
,trof eert eht kcatta ot detnaw dah utS nehT
”.su htiw emoc t’nac ehS
”.emit tsrif eht ,oot ,em deracs tI .neppah ti teL .dE ,yako s’tI“
.htaerb ym gnihctac kcor a no gnittis saw I dna ,oga sraey owt saw tI   -   .ton ,lleW
.edisni morf esion delfits a
”.esuoh eht ni god a s’ereht kniht I
.ekoj a si siht ekil gnitca lla er’uoY !yrc ot gniog ton m’I“
?ti t’nsaw ,kcab shtnom net ,detrats d’ti woh s’taht dnA
tog uoY .ton ylbaborP“   .deksa semaJ
.sredluohs ym no sdnah tlef I
.niaga truh racs yM .gniremmis dna toh wolley
eno s’taht ,dE !woW“
.edistuo delbmuts I sa em rof yaw edam utS
.gib yllaeR .gib saw god ehT
,won taen erew sracs eht hguoht nevE
”?em tiH ?od ot tnaw uoy od tahw oS ?yrc ton ,hO“   ”…m’I …m’I
htworgrednu eht tlef I
.oga shtnom esoht lla ,tfel d’I nehw sa
ylleb reh no ekoms thgil a morf ,derruf-yerg saw ehS
.pu teef thgie morf llef I sa
.su dnuora degguh smrA
.redluohs reh fo kcab eht no saw ’sseB
racs ym tsuj saw tI .der yrev neve ro ,niks ym rednu gnilwarc ro ,gnideelb t’nsaw ti ,on tub
.deneppah dah tI erehw s’taht dna
,daeh ym revo delias trad fren rehtonA .deksa I
.deneppah ti nehw erehT
,truoc elttil ruo dloh ot su fo ruof eht rof hguone ediw saw tI
.tsehc ym ni rettulf traeh ym edam ti taht
,etib a ni ecaf ym thguac tI
dna stoor dna trid
.daeh ym ni did ti naht tnereffid dekool ylbaborp ti ,tniop siht yB
.sderhs ni roolf tserof eht ot rettulf—stnap dna—trihs ym was I .tsrub ti nehT
”.hguor yllaer saw ti tilps stnerap ym
ereht doots tsuj lla ew oS
.si ti woh swonk semaJ“
,liat yarg a fo hsalf lanoisacco eht was ylno ew os
,yks eht ni wol nus eht derebmemer I nehT
fo demaerd t’ndah I
laeuqs deticxe na htiW
.yako s’tI .yako s’tI“
.nwod kcab ot gnilliw su fo rehtien
,traeh ym htiw emit ni demmurht ydob elohw yM
,denruter I hcihw ,thgindoog guh a em evag utS
,sedis eht ot tuo denettalf srae ehT
.erofeb aera siht ni nees neeb reven
.pag wen eht dnuora etargetnisid ot detrats
,sdnah reh otni lotsip freN a dehsup semaJ .deddon dna
.ksed sih ta saw daD
.knurt eert wolloh eht ni pag dellif-nus eht tuo deddon I ”.meht dnA
.tuo yaw sti no ylniatrec saw noonretfa eht tub ,krad t’nsaw tI .senip eht dniheb deppid dah nus eht ,hguone nooS
.ton ro ot detnaw I rehtehw gniog saw I dna
.ti dellac utS ,ria eht ni elihW   .ti deppilf dna
.emoh emoc yllanif d’I wenk I
”.skcus eno no owT
,tip dnas eht gnidnefed yrotciv demialc I dna sseB   .dezigolopa sseB
.moor ym ot pu dettort dna em dniheb mals rood eht tel I
.gnikcal ylraelc erew meht fo egdelwonk dnah-dnoces ruo dna
tuoba lla su gnillet ,niaga gnirettahc detrats dah utS
”!reverof enog erew uoy thguoht I
,moorhtab eht esu ot flesym desucxe I
.emit siht esnefed rieht dleh syob eht
,snosaer suoirav roF
,sracs ruo yb denioJ
.ti naem t’ndid I“
,daeh reh dekcud ehS ”.haeY“
.hteet wolley dna seye wolleY
.did ew tahw won uoy llet t’ndluoc I tub ,semag erom deyalp ew taht wonk I
thguac ehS   ”!sliaT“
,gniog saw I dalg saw I taht reh dlot I oS
.llams gnihtemos s’ti fi erac t’nod I
dnuora denrut saw daeh sih tub
stekcop snaej reh fo eno fo tuo retrauq a dehsif ehS
.keehc ym rednu gnihctiwt saw racs yM
.niks krad reh tsniaga thgirb tuo doots hteet reh dna
,semaJ saw ti kniht I
,ecnef a fo pot no gnihcuorc neeb d’eh erehw morf nwod debmilc utS
,tsirw ym fo dne eht no ti tlef I
.moc.enilnoyxof.www
.niaga evael ot evah thgim I ,shtnom wef a ni dnA .tfel d’I
”.elpoep ta lworg t’ndluohs sgoD“ ,dias dna
.swaP .sdnah sti ni sevil ruo dleh d’ti dna
,tsap sraey emoS
.hguorht dekconk neeb d’ehs erehw dniheb sehsub eht ni diks a saw erehT
.epolevne eht gnidloh llits saw eH
.mad rieht edam srevaeb eht erehw
.deksa sseB ”?su htiw emoc t’nac uoy taht uoy llet I fi od ot gniog uoy era tahW“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”!selohssa uoY …uoY“
.spil sti morf gnilgnad loord ees dluoc I dna
)rezeerf eht ni xob a morf selffaw detsaot dah daD(
.yad taht snaej sih gniraew neeb t’ndah eh esuaceb ,flac sih no saw ’semaJ
.erew sesiri sti roloc tahw llet t’ndluoc I raf os detalid slipup dna ediw seye ,wol daeH
,rorrim eht ni kool ot moorhtab eht ot tnew I
,esruoc fo ,t’ndid I
.eciohc ym saw ti fi sA
noos krad gnitteg eb ot gniog saw ti taht rednimer a saw enohp gnizzub ehT
.ti naem t’ndid I yas ot em rof gnitiaw
,devlovni seitrap lla gnoma tnemeerga nekopsnu na saw ereht ,revewoH
.kooh sti morf nug htruof eht deerf I dna
,em ta derats ehs won oS   .tfel I neht dnA
.won nrut s’yob eht saw ti tnaem hcihw
.raW a rof nosrep rehtona dedeen eW .dooG“
noitatS dlo eht no diar a yb dewollof ,tserof peed eht ot kcab devom dna depmaced ew os
esuoh eht otni deppets sseB nehw
,roloc tnereffid emos seog ti fi ro ,gnitruh speek ti fI
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,detuohs dna nwod detniop sseB ,sselraeF
sdneirf llits erew ew tsael ta tub
,niaga llaw eht tsniaga depmuj tI .daeh
.pu ekops semaJ ,tfel ym oT
.gnizamA   …tlef I …tlef I
.em no erew seye s’enoyrevE   ”!?dE“   lerdnaK yb
.eromyna ti fo trap t’nsaw I
.niaga evael ot deen thgim I taht saw nekopsnU
.og ti tel eh tub
.deniamer llits taht rood eht fo edis rehto eht nepo ot gniyrt
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
?kcaP eht ni eb ot tnaw uoY
.evila saw I .eerf saw I
snebuR gnikam saw mom sih taht decnuonna dna
,tsrif tops terces ruo fo tuo dehsad utS
,srae trela dna elzzum prahs
ekil eb ot gniog saw ehs fi
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.eseehC n‘ sknarF ym otni
”!yad siht llaf t’now tiP ehT“
.erom yna ksa t’ndid I os
.t’ndid eh tub ,tnemom yna ni daeh sih kcits ot dad detcepxe I
.su htiw reh gnirb attog ew ,no emoC“
.yako ton s’tI“ .detuohs I ”!oN“
.ecaf ym dekorts dna yawa dellup sseB
.denruter d’I taht tnemeticxe sih htiw gnola hctip ni gniworg eciov dehctip-hgih sih ,demialcxe utS
.sraet ym otni delims ehS
.thginot esnefed eht no erew ew dna ,em dna utS saw ti tnaem tahT
”.reh ees ot tnaw I .hguorht em teL“
.kcab derats ehs dna ,reh ta derats I
.thgiew sti morf srebmit fo kaerc eht draeh I dna
depsalc semaJ dna ,maercs a htiw nwod tnew utS
,tfel llits remmus eht fo flah elohw a saw erehT
,yletarucca erom ,rO .delbmum I
.hteet wohs ot kcab deleep spil eht dna
.deksa I ”?ydal taC“
.ria eht ni taolf raews eht tel I
.keehc ym no racs eht yllaicepse ,tib a dehca gnihtyrevE
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.remmus siht em ot noitnetta hcum gniyap eb ot mees t’ndid daD dna moM tub
.dezeens d’I ekil saw tI
nepo gnigniws fo daetsni dna
nevaeh detsaot ekil detsat dna
,emit siht eert eht fo tuo dekconk teg ot eno tsrif eht saw I
.su rof hguone terces saw tahT
.deneppah dah tI ecnis ton—
.ylivaeh gnihtaerb llits saw ehS ”.duorp m’I …m’I
elfir pu-taeb dlo eht em dednah utS elihw
.mih tih I erehw tsehc sih ta yllacitamard
.noom eht no gnihsif tnew ohw tac a tuoba saw tI .did eh os
).emoh ta dah reve d’ew elacs yna ekil kool t’ndid ti hguoht(
.yawa dekool ehs sa deyaws riah reh fo slruc dliw ehT .dias sseB ”.huH“
.no ti thguorb dah—
,segnih detsur sti fo eerf rood eht raet ot deganam sseB
,rood-elbuod eht fo sniamer eht ta deggut sseB
.tlef I tahw s’tahT
!hcnup a saw tahT
.klaw t’nseod gniK eht esuaceb ,sredluohs ruo no deirrac eb dluohs ehs taht deerced sseB gniK
,dray kcab ’semaJ ni riaffa lausac a saw hcnuL
.dnuorg eht ot waP .dnuorg eht ot dnah a htiw flesym thguac dna deppirt I
.ni tuc sseB   .gniyas saw utS
.sretsef tlefnu dna
.deid dah regna ym fo erif eht tuB
,ediw erew seye siH
”.elbirroH …gnieb stnerap
.gnitcirtsnoc em dnuora gnihtemos tlef I
llems eht tuoba demaerd I   -   .kcaP eht
”?yako ,worromot uoy ees ll’eW .dE ,gib gnihton s’tI .yako s’tI“
.tfel I fi kcap eht fo tuo saw I dias ehs oS
,lerdnaK yb ”kcaP ehT“
htiw snootrac lla neeb d’yehT
,niaga snug freN eht htiw gniyalp meht thguac I ,resolc dekaens I nehW
esuoh a fo snoitadnuof eht dnuora llaw dlo na erew no tas ew senots ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.noitinumma tneps sih retfa desahc semaJ
.tserof eht otni deraeppasid meht fo eerht eht neht
,sgel neewteb liaT
,emoh eb ot desoppus saw I
krad eht ni seye fo noitcelfer eht dna
.sdneirf ym htiw gnieb deyojne tsuj dna seye ym desolc I
”.elbirroh saw tI .raey siht snikneJ .srM dah I“
.syawla ,ti dediova ew oS
.reh ta lworg ot egru elbatsiserri eht dah I   ”?yrC“
.pmuj ot derehtag sdnih dna
,mih evas ot deirt dah semaJ
.gninetsil-flah ylno saw I
.gniyrc saw I ebyam os ,yakO
”.kcaP ruoy ot kcab emocleW
utS dnuora smra ym depparw I
.yltnecer tserof fo hctap elttil siht hguorht emoc d’ti wenk I tub ,tibbar a ees t’ndid I
,sgod tuoba klat ot diarfa saw llits daD dna ,retal sraey owt saw I ereH
.em dniheb pu emac ehs sa dezeehw sseB
,reh htiw em gnikat saw moM
.ecuas htiw gnippird erew taht sehciwdnas dah ew erehw
.eergasid t’ndluoc I
,tops terces ruo ta t’nsaw kcaP ehT
.llaw a dehcnup d’I ekil gnibborht
.etalocohc reh tsniaga niks maerC
-   .ffo erew I dna utS dna ,gnitnuoc detrats semaJ ”…owt ,enO“
,tlefnu si diasnu dnA
”kcaP ehT“ saw sihT
.laes rieht sa ti desu ecitcarp ,s’lebeiS .srM
.em dniheb morf dias utS
.meht htiw gnimoc em tsniaga eno ot-owt saw ti nehw toN
.seldeen enip fo hcuot eht dna ,retaw fo
.erusaem doog rof seeb elbmub wef a dna shtom fo ynoloc a htiw revopeels a gnidloh erew yeht tniop siht yb dna
.em ta delwocs ehS
,lufrednow detsat gnihtemoS
,ecaf reh ssorca daerps elims A
”!moor emos reh evig ,owt uoy no emoC !ho—
.erofeb eno nees reven d’ew hguoht
.nekatsim neeb d’I yltnerappa tub ,edis ym no saw semaJ thguoht d’I wohemoS
.pu nrot lla saw keehc ym esuaceb ytterp em dnif reve dluow eno on taht em dlot ehs dna
,trams a thguac I ,ruf no thgilnus fo hsalf eht nI
.suoires dekool sseB ,emit sihT ”.ton er’uoY .era eW“
.noitadilav ym fo devirped ylbuod won
.xeneelk a otni eson sih welb dna edis eht ot denrut eH
.ecneirepxe ot em rof ereht saw
.rood neercs eht hguorht noitasrevnoc a draeh I denruter I nehw dna
.noitnetta sih deen t’ndid tub tespu saw I taht wonk daD tel og ot deen eht tlef I
.deddap tlef tsomla yeht talf os dna thgilnus eht morf mraw
repap fo eceip a saw dnah sih nI
,egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac
.god eht ees dluoc ew
tsuj yeht t’ndluoC ?meht ot traeh ym gnirab saw I nehw ,em ta gnilims eh saw yhW !?yhW ?tahW .nirg
.llew sa did stnerap s’kcaP eht fo tser eht ylbamuserp sa ,saw ti erehw wenk—
.thgir osla saw ehS .tcaf-fo-rettam os ti dias ehS ”.did uoy tuB“
em ta depael eh nehw
.uoy rof gnitiaw tsuj erew ew—wenk syawla eW
,hguoht ,etirovaf sih saw tI
.hguoht ,gnilims t’nsaw sseB
.pirg ym rednu deyaws tI
.tuo dnif t’ndid eh taht tnatropmi saw ti os ,nwonk d’eh fi su pots ylbaborp d’eH
.detcejretni semaJ
,gnizzub detrats ti nehW .tes dah daD taht
,no tis ot tlef yeht woh rebmemer I .spot htooms dna
.tuo yaw ym no mih derongi I tub ,denialpmoc utS