”speelS noiL ehT“:yojne esaelP
.thgin tsal fo yromem eht ta hctarcs ot deirt yelnatS dna
.yrros m'I .yelnatS hO"
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.oga skeew owt elas dray a morf emoh ti deggard dah eninaJ
.setunim ytnewt tsal eht ni elim a flah naht ssel devom d'yehT
.reidaeb denrut seye siH
.tipmra sih otni tib rednib eht fo segde eht ylthgit os troper eht ot gnulc dna
.siht ekil retteb sdnuos tI .dad ,yako s'tI"
.denekrad ecaf reh dna
.niaga etal saw eH
.stfihs thginrevo derusaem yltcefrep eviF
"?ssertsid ni uoy erA"
natS elttil htiw hcuoc eht no pu gnilruc deppiks
.liat gnol sih dehsiws dna
.ylno edis eno ot ylprahs dehctiwt elzzum sih dna dehgis eH
ecalperif eht fo dneirf yb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sgel resuort sih ni deggans swalc siH
.eciffo eht fo dne etisoppo eht ta smoor gniteem eht drawot delffuhs dna mra tuots eno rednu tnuocca enruobleM eht gniniatnoc rednib drah eht dehctulc yelnatS
kcab eht ni stam dah llits enam siH
,noitomorp sih kaerb ro ekam dluow gninrom siht noitatneserp ehT
,depoord liat siH
.dray rebmul eht ta ytiruces gniod keew a sruoh ytroF
walc eno htiw wodniw eht derewol eH
,thgir eht no yb evord flow A
.dnirg hteet raer s'yelnatS edam taht egnar a otni dehctip eciov lesaew siH
elum a ekil nar ti tub
.won delwoh snroh ehT
.slirtson sih gnikohc eeffoC
.taerht a mih redisnoc dluow yelnatS erofeb evorp ot erom tol a dna
.seye sih desolc dna
.teiuq dna ecin deyats gnihtyreve erus gnikam dna
.yllufituaeb tuo kcen eht dehcterts dah renwo suoiverp eht dna
.noitcerid s'yelnatS ni gnuws selzzum rieht llA
,nos sih fo seye ediw eht ta nwod derats ,swaj sih denepo yelnatS
nepo seye sih peek ot stnap tius sih tsniaga swalc sih fo spit eht desu eH
.niaga gnilims ,yawrood eht ni deraeppa eninaJ ,emit sihT
?niaga hcuoc eht no peelsa nellaf roinuj daH
,seye s'relttaW fo gnitniuqs ehT
.selit nehctik eht ssorca dehcram dna
.rennid revo thgin tsal eninaJ ta delrans d'eH
"?riS" .noisserpxe gnidnecsednoc
.104 eht no peelsa lleF"
.moor gniteem eht morf secap net mih deppots ,ssergorp sih dellats eciov s'dlareG "!yelnatS"
".lla ta derit ton m'I" .delbmur dna
.tnuocca enruobleM eht no gnikrow thgin tsal etal oot pU
,etaicossa regnuoy a no dellac relttaW .rM ",siweL"
dednuos dah eciov s'eninaJ
leeh reh no nups eninaJ ".rennid
.tlep nedlog sih dewohs taht pag eht dna
puc maoforytS gnimaets a dna ,gnaf hcum oot dewohs taht nirg gib a
,trihs krow sih fo noitcirtsnoc eht morf deerF
,tnuocca reniarb on a saw tI
.snoilednad htiw dedduts nwal a ssorca ylippah dednuob dna
.niaga derekcilf seye reH
.won feeb dnuorg ot desu teg retteb d'yehT
.wodniw sih no drah dekconk gnihtemoS
",sgnivas emos evah eW"
.emoh wen sih gnicaf pu tas dna
,mra eno rednu rednib a dah siweL
.senal eht fo segde eht ta detfil sreniater etercnoc htoomS
.ti ni ehtaerb ot moor fo stoL
,derepsihw daeh sih revo seert ehT
,noisseccus ni semit eerht detaeper eh taht dnuos yciuj a ,delffins roinuJ
.reh tsap derats dna
,tsehc sih ni tliub raor ehT
.reddal eht pu kcab derebmalc nos sih sa
.gniroolf teuqrap eht no eciwt
elgnuj etercnoc eht dna
.yadot laed namdetS eht ot netsil annoG" .nihc
".diarfa m'I ,seirettab sdeen kcurt ruoY"
"—cca enruobleM eht tog ev'I"
.reh ot yas ot tahw fo kniht ot deirt dna doots yelnatS ".tsaf
.wap rehto eht htiw ralloc sih ta deggut dna
,iluaP secnarF ecalperif eht fo dneirf yb ”speelS noiL ehT“
,mra eht no pat a dik eht evag regdab dlo eht nehw ,llitS
moor gnivil eht ot ti dewollof yelnatS .pat-pat-pat .paT
.yawrednu ydaerla gniteeM
.enam sih ta yllufniap deggut taht
nottub gnissim eht ot
?VT hcum oot hctaw eh diD
.leehw gnireets depparw-rehtael eht ni seloh tniopnip kcirp
.ezeerb eht no mih ot detfird eciov s'eninaJ "?yelnatS"
",egnahc ot etunim a deen tsuJ"
.edils taht ,tnemtsevni taerg A
.seohs delos-kcils sih rednu dessih teprac ehT
.denepo srood rotavele eht erofeb eeffoc eht dellems eH
.gnippan ni tseretni on dah eh dnuof dna
.pih sih ta regnif tuots a detniop dna
.niaga dils dna delaeuqs buc sih dna
mra sih rednu morf tuo rednib enruobleM eht deirp yelnatS  ?deb ot gnimoC
.rehtael eht tsniaga kcab mih desserp tleb redluohs sih tub
,ecno toof a deppat
,yralas s'htnom a mih tsoc dah ledomer nehctik ehT
.triks rengised reh revo deit norpa eht no swap reh depiw eninaJ "?tekcit rehtonA"
.tuo saw eh elihw deppohs eninaJ
.mih gnillik erew stnemyap raC
.thgilnus noonretfa eht detcelfer seye s'eninaJ "?erus uoy erA"
,ffirdim tnangerp reh revo dehcterts sserd reH
.rehtie esac sih gniugra fo ytilibissop oN
.rac sih detartlifni tsuahxe fo knits eht dna dehcnub enam siH
depacse rethgual fo tsalb A
.niaga denethgit taorht siH
,yawrood gniteem eht dehcaer yelnatS ".104
.gnimaercs snroH ...emit ekam d'eH
.rennid hsinif ot gniog m'I"
.tekcit rehtona tog I dnA"
.eeffoc a barc ot emit oN
.derrulb mih dnuora srac eht ni secaf eht dna
,ecalperiF ehT fO sdneirF ruoy morf sunob elttil a s’ereh ,desimorp sa dnA
.wodniw edis revird sih depmuht tsif nat A  .PAT
.hteet s'yelnatS delttar gniknoh fo dnuor rehtonA
.eno elttil ,rennid rof hsaw oG"
edis eno ot dekcor kcommah ehT
,waj sih otni yaw sti dekrow nway a
.dehcterts dna dehcterts htuom sih dna
.delruc eugnot siH
.ebyam ,keew txen emitemos foor eht no kroW
,kcolc draobhsad sih ta deralg yelnatS
sih no ruf eht hguorht wap a dehsurb relttaW ".yadsendeW
.taorht sih otni tib ralloc s'yelnatS
.egnahc ot yawllah eht nwod delffuhs yelnatS
.yek ffo delaeuqs kcurt erif s'natS elttil fo neris ynnit eht
.yawa meht detfil ehs nehw deniamer stnirp etihw-ruolf niwT
.nroh dehsilop ekil detnilg seye s'relttaW
".elcihev siht evom ot deen uoY"
.kcen sih ot pu yaw eht lla tnew taht evren a gnihcnip
reyof eht ni doots yelnatS ".lliw
.edils sih fo pot eht morf delwoh natS elttiL ".wwwA"
!sunob elttil a rof edosipe siht fo dne eht ta dnuora kcits dnA
.sredluohs s'yelnatS ta deparcs dnuos tahT
"!yddaD"  .neris yot a fo
.retteb shparg eht wohs ot sthgil eht ffo tuhs enoemoS
.ecafrus eht ram ot hctarcs elgnis a tuohtiw demaelg selit rieht won tub
?ehs t'ndah ,thgin tsal peelsa neeb dah ehS
.gnivird eb ot derit ooT ".tsuj saw I ...m'I"
.eerf dnuos eht tel dna yruf sih dnuora dehcterts ,denepo waj s'yelnatS
...ecnis neeb ti dah gnol woH
.tuo yaw eht no gnis ot gniunitnoc tub gnidaf ,delbraw kcurt yot ehT
.lla ta gnikrow ton m'I woN"
.rood s'revird sih revo depard swap s'poc ehT "!riS .riS"
.hcrop eht no doots efiw siH
,ikahK  yb uoy rof daer ,iluaP secnarF
.puc maoforytS ,gnimaets a gniyrrac elcibuc sih fo tuo delddaw dlareG
.delruc pil s'yelnatS
.enips sih gnola noitnetta ot riah fo egdir a delkcit
,tnorftrihs s'yelnatS ot deppord seye s'dlareG "?gninrom hguoR"
.gnikrow draobyek sih revo dehcnuh thgin llA ".yadot
trihs-t a dna staews no tup dna delworg eH
.yaw rehtie etal eb d'eh dna
,dekcut neeb dah riahc yrevE
ralloc sih ta deggut yelnatS
.depoord sdileye siH
.ygolopa na delims dna
.devaw dna elcibuc ybraen a morf pu deppop
laeuqs gniyd eht dna
.enam sih ni staM
.efas eb ot tsuj niaga swercs eht nethgit d'eH
.epacse dluoc dnuos eht erofeb dewollaws dna
.denepo rood moor gniteem ehT
eeffoc eht morf yawa ezag sih deggard ,deknilb eH
.leets sselniats ni enohs secnailppa ehT
.noitom eht htiw kcab dna
,epols trohs a fo pot eht ta detser emoh elibom riehT
.ekops dik eht elihw
.seninac dewolley ffo dewohs dna
daeh sih revo smra sih dehcterts eH ".eruS"
.ti dnuora delruc eugnot knip s'yelnatS
.rac sih fo tnorf ni enal eht ni ecaps ytpme eht ta depag dna
,eson sih desaet amora eeffoc ehT
.peels hguone ton dna eeffoc hcum ooT
"!enog lla tsomla s'eno sihT"
.rac rehtie rof llams oot saw taht pag eht otni egrem ot gniyrt neeb d'ohw
.yaweerf tseraen eht morf selim ytriht doog a dna
.noitatneserp sih rof etal yletinifed won dna devirped peels ooT
.tsap delbma dna delims dlareG ".kcoldirg
.kcoldirg nmaD" ".niagA"
,dne raf eht morf mih dehctaw ssob siH
.trihs-t sih ni eloh eht hguorht walc a dekop yelnatS
.esiar eht dedeen eh dna
.dessim d'eh peels fo sruoh ynam woh mih dednimer
,seye reh otni derats yelnatS ".yako
.delbmur tsehc s'yelnatS
.enam esned fo elppir a dna pans a htiw pu daeh sih thguorb
....egalliv reparcsyks eht raeN
,dlareG dekil eH
.srae sih gnillif slamina gnirettahC
,thgiarts dna taen
"!eeeeW" #  .decnad niam dettam sih litnu
.gninrom siht ydaer teg ot dehsur d'eh erehw
.....elgnuj etercnoc eht ,elgnuj eht nI
cra na ni kcurt eht gnuws buc ehT ".siht
.ediw htuom sih dehcterts
.dniw dah d'yeht emit tsal eht eerf dekrow dah selgnihs fo pirts A
sleeh sih otno kcab dekcor ,dettauqs eH
ot togrof dna edis rehto eht ot kcab gniws ot tnaem dah ti fi sa ereht gnignah
.gniyub rebmemer t'ndid eh taht repmah a otni yrdnual ytrid sih werht eH
,rood sih edistuo tfel dah roinuj llab rebbur eht ta dekcik eH
taem fo llems ehT
.ecnalab rof delialf dna
ylduorp deddon natS elttiL ".huh-
.mih drawot gnidnuob dna
sgel s'rehtom sih neewteb gnihsup dna
.yelnatS fo thgis eht ta
,regnif elddim yerg yzzuf a mih deppilf
.kcab dna krow ot mih tog dna
.taorht s'yelnatS ni degdol lworg A  ".pu tiaW"
.edils latem ,gnol eht nwod dehsoohw dna delaeuqs natS elttiL
.edis rehtie no ni dezeeuqs rac retfa raC
eohs s'regdab dlo na fo
.mih fo tnorf ni elbat eht no ti dial dna
.yako eb ll'eW" .dias ehs
hU" ".gnidaf era stops ruoY"  "?dad ,seY" ".noS"
.yawllah eht otni teg ot
.rehtegot dekcilc hteet s'yelnatS
.ecaf nwo sih ta degnirc dna
ralloc trihs sih otni regnif derruf a deffuts eH
.tuo deffuns noitasrevnoc eht ,sdrow s'regdab eht tA ".era uoy erehT"
,nugeb ydaerla dah yad eciffo ehT
.tsal eht naht reduol emit hcae
.elbat eht tsniaga kcab
.tfel yeht erofeb stlob eht nethgit d'eH .dias yelnatS
esolc seye sih tel dna
,mih dnuora ezah a ni gninrom fo tnecs eht detfaw eeffoc fo spuc evlewT
.dnilb flah mih evord wolg s'neercs eht elihw noisiv larehpirep sih otni gninrub pmal ksed tniopnip ehT
tlit drawnwod eht
.gnilahni fo ekatsim eht edam dna
.deb otni delwarc eh nehw thgil a ekil tuo neeb dah eninaJ "?yelnatS"
deddon dna ,deknilb
rorrim yawyrtne eht htaeneb gep eht no tekcaj sih gnuh eH ".tekcit
,pu depmuj yelnatS
gnihtyalp s'nos sih fo gnihceercs eht erehw
s'poC .wodniw sih fo emarf erauqs eht otni denael ecaf terref keels A
.taorht sih morf yawa cirbaf eht deggut dna
erusserp neddus a yawa deknilb yelnatS
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
?emit no ti ekam d'eh sddo eht erew tahW
.lliw tI .enif eb ll'tI
.ti no ruolf tog ehs fi ecalper ot droffa t'ndluoc eh esuolb eht fo tnorf eht revo dessorc sdnah reH
.noos edaf dluow stops s'roinuJ
.yawevird rieht ni dekrap rac desu A
?deb ot enog yllanif eh dah emit tahW
"?gnideepS"  .tiag gnildnurt
rehtael eht delppits
”speelS noiL ehT“ saw sihT
.emit ni dekcud yelnatS ,emit sihT
.yalp buc sih dehctaw dna edis sih otno dellor yelnatS dna
gnitten eht revo sgel sih gnuws
.eeffoc emos dedeen yelnatS ,doG
#  .seye kcalb ydaeb s'relttaW .rM ni
ssenkrad eht gniklaW
.gniknoh hcum oS  .nepo dna
,enips sih gnola eci werht eciov s'relttaW "!yelnatS"
,rood edis s'revird raer eht no lenap detsur a dah tI
.won droffa dluoc yeht naht erom tsoc emoh sih ni gnihtyrevE .evisnepxE
.nottub pot sih ffo pans ot ecrof hguone htiw drawpu desserp raor ehT "...ot deen uoY"
sreliart rehto yb dednuorrus
,ylleb sih tsniaga nos sih fo thgiew eht koot eH
,liat nwo sih no deppets yelnatS
.pu thguac dlareG elihw
.ti elfits dluoc ehs erofeb raef htiw derekcilf
,trihs eulb ,tah
.efil ot kcab ti gnirb ot stlob wef a dna tniap fo taoc a koot ylno tI
eramthgin a otni xnyl eht nevird evah t'ndluow
.trihs etirovaf siH
hsur looc a tlef
.yadsendeW ot kcab ti dehsup ev'eW"
,mih dniheb tuo delgna sraC
.tsaf os gniworg s'eH"
htrof dna kcab dekcor tes gniws dehcatta ehT
emalf llihc a gnithgil dna
swalc sih fo spit eht tel dna selkcunk ynwat dexelf yelnatS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.moor rieht ot llah eht nwod yaw reh no tsap gnitfird ,yawa raf
,oot ,buc sih htiw emit VT deppiks d'eH .krow ta krow ot emit elttil os
.dnuorgkcab eht ni no VT
.sgel ynwat reh dnuora derettulf striks eht
?moordeb rieht otni ssacrac yrros sih deggard eh nehw ,neeb ti dah emit tahW
.sdrawkcab gnignirc dna swap raer sih no gnidnal ,deppord nos siH
.klat ot deen ew kniht I"
.dnuorg eht dehsurb
kcihc hateehc eht morf gniknoh yrgna erom denwaps dna
ylimaf on htiw xnyl a
.senomorehp dna semuf tsuahxe htiw sgnul sih dellif htaerb peed A
.buc sih fo gniraor deticxe eht ta delims ,deddon yelnatS ".eruS" ".rennid
.rehtegot dekcilc sgnaf siH ".lleW"
.rennid rof emoc ot su tnaw s'notsnhoJ ehT"
nwot ni erots tfirht eht ta rallod A .yfmoC
,noitcerid eno ylno dehctiwt eson siH
.tey nwo etiuq t'ndid eh rehtael eht ni tup tsuj d'eh seloh eht revo ylitliug wap sih dehsurb yelnatS
.shgiht sih no swap sih tup yelnatS
.eman sih derepsihw ydobemos ,erehwemoS
,wodniw sih dekcarc eH
si yrots s’yadot dna
,moor gnivil eht morF
,delttar dleihsdniw ehT
.thginot gnihctaw denigami dna denway yelnatS
.pirg s'yelnatS fo eerf ti gnikconk ylraen
,kcab dereggats eH
.edis eno ot daeh sih detlit dna
.raef erom tol A .regnA
.elprup htiw demmir seye dna nottub gnissim A
.eson depirts sih fo
eot ot daeh morf mih denimaxe ehS
,yawa derepmacs buc riehT   ".eno
.thginoT" "?emit tahW"
,leehw eht no pirg sih denethgit yelnatS
efil sih fo tnecs larutan
edils eht nwod dekaerts buc rieht dna ,delims ehS
.enal dnah-tfel eht dekcolb yletelpmoc elcihev s'poc eht elihw thgir eht no tsap desae
regguR puplluB ,dnaloR
.rof yap ot elba eb ot desoppus saw eh taht sgniht detcelloc eninaJ
,seires aitnepreS eht fo rohtua
.denethgit spil s'eninaJ ".lla
.selcibuc ytpme fo dirg a decaf yelnatS ,detrap slenap revlis eht nehw dna
.nihc sih tsniaga kcurt citsalp eht fo kconk drah eht dna
,selcanam emaceb tsirw sih dnuora sffuc ehT
.yub ot mih rof sgniht eroM .gniyd seirettaB
,edis eht ot kcommah eht dekcor yelnatS "?haeY"
.nihc sih gnibbur ,deddon dna
.ni yaw eht no tekcit a toG"
.flesmih decarb yelnatS
iluaP secnarF yb
.niaga tuhs ti sa ylprahs ffo tuc neht dna
.yawllah eht ni tsaor ekil dellems tI
sevael daehrevo eht hguorht gniretlif nus ehT
,ruf ynwat sih revo snrettap delttom tsac
denway yelnatS .efas ti peeK
,tnuocca enruobleM eht depmub redluohs yzzuf siH
.deliaw neris yot ehT
,mih ta derats ehS
.eninaJ rof emoh ecin gnihtemos gnirb d'eH
,yawa ecnuob ti dehctaw
,gnicnad moor eht ssorca sniatruc eht gnittes ,deraor eH
.neercs noitcejorp eht ediseb morf
.reh rof hcaer neve ot derit oot neeb d'eh dna
.ssenidrat s'dlareG fo noitnem oN ".retfa enin s'tI"
.teprac nrow eht tsniaga
.tius eht htaeneb hctiwt ruf sih edam
.wwwA" ".tsrif pan a tnaw d'uoy meht dlot I
#  .noitartsurf s'yelnatS fo ecrof lluf eht htiw deohce
kcuhcdoow pmulp ehT
.dehcnip ecaf regdab s'relttaW .rM
.moc.iluapsecnarf no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
gnippat eht ni deid taht epoh fo ffihw a
.sdneirf tsaf emoceb dah rood txen dik enarc eht dna natS elttiL
.mih nioj dna pu yrruh ot dlareG delliw dna gniteem eht drawot deppets eH ".ni
,liat sih dehsiws ,detiaw eH
...raor t'nod ,gnilrad ym hsuH
,wols a rekrow-oc sih evag sgel tuots ehT
.enildaed thgit a evah t'ndid laed namdetS ehT .wap eerf sih ni
,reh ediseb ni deltsen eh nehw dehctiwt t'ndah ehS
llab rebbur eht otno delbmuts
.yaweerf eht no rehtegot degdew selcihev fo dworc eht edisni erehwemos deralb nroh A
.elbat gnol eht ta riahc ytpme tsal eht ni tas dna edisni kcuhcdoow eht dewollof yelnatS
.yltnesba ruf ylleb sih dehctarcs eH
.tuo saw yad eht erofeb stlob eht nethgit dluohs eH
.tcapmi hcae ta degnirc dna
.tpels eh elihw deitpme dah moor gniteem ehT ".klat
.peels fo ssol dna sruoh etal fo
wap eno ni kcurt erif eht gnigniws ,teprac hsulp eht morf tpael nos siH
.hctaw sih tsniaga ycarucca sti dekcehc
,denediw seye s'eninaJ "?derif erew uoY"
.sllaw eht tsniaga depmuht liat s'yelnatS
,enod noitatneserp eht teg ot erusserp hcum os tsuJ
thgir sih no pu desae ovloV a ni ung A
.liaw s'neris a fo yrcimim riaf a ni delwoh dna
,yaw gnorw eht debbur yeht ,woN
.derekcilf neercs noitcejorp ehT
.taorht sih otni delbmur
.drow a draeh t'ndah eh dna ,gnivom saw htuom s'kcuhcdoow ehT
deknilb eH .pat-pat-pat ,paT
".yelnatS ,drah oot gnikrow er'uoY"
,tfos eht delahni yelnatS
,ti fo secart eht llems llits dluoc yelnatS tub ,srekrowoc sih htiw tfel dah eeffoc ehT
edit a ekil tuo hsaw edisni noitasrevnoc eht tel dna nepo ti dleh
,ozirraC gnirutaef
.denrut rehtaew eht erofeb nwod meht kcat ot evah d'eH
.slaP rewoP hctaw ot gnidneterp dna
dessap eh sa eenk eht no rehtaf sih gnikconk
.regnol hcum nam dlo sih htiw eldduc ot tnaw t'ndluow eH