.snoitasrevnoc rieht lla fo dnuorgkcab eht ni
yojne esaelP  .su fo lla rof
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,ecaep ni no og dluow efil sih neht dna
,redlo tey werg eh nehW
.rucco dluow snoitasrevnoC
retfa ,llits redlo tey werg eh
.nocaeb elttil a ,langis elttil a emoceb
,tes ot nageb nus eht nehw oS
?war llits saw dnuow eht esuaceb ti fo kaeps ot tnaw ton did dna ,yltnecer ffo eno kaerb eh diD
.sevlesmeht sevlow ton tsom
.esle gnihtyna rof emit elttil os tfel syawla hcihw ,llewd ot emit hguonE
,syawla sa ,enola ,emoh gninruter
sgnirehtag laicos ot gnirb ot hsiw ton did eh mohw draknurd a saw ehs ebyaM  ?mih desuba ro
.snoitaler nwo sih ,seugaelloc sih ,sdneirf sih
,retawhtab lohocla taht no gnitfird reh fo llems eht ,eciov reh fo dnuos eht ,reh fo thgis ehT
.mih teem lla dluoc yeht os wollef ykcul eht gnirb ot elba eb dluow ehs emit txen taht epoh dluoW
sgnilkni laicos dah eh ,sevlow tsom ekil dna ,flow a saw eH
,regnorts worg dluow tnecs eht ,elihw a rof
,emit ot emit morf ecneserp sih ni tnecs siht teg dluow sevlow rehto ,oot ,yad eht ni kcaB
,dessertsid etiuq werg srentrap tuohtiw llits sdneirf sih fo esoht
.kcab thgil rehtona ticile ot gnitcepxe ,meht neewteb flug krad eht ni thgil elttil A
,teliot eht rof flesreh esucxe dluow ehs ,tniop emos ta oS
,eno on htiw emac ohw rehtonA
spahrep gnimoceb dna steliot eht esu ot ycneuqerf gnisaercni htiw tuo gnippets
,yaw siht no tnew ti fI
,kcap ot :sevlow fo yaw eht saw tahT
.tnemegagne s'asilannA etarbelec ot ,thginot gniknird tuo gniog erew sevlow rehto eht fo emos dna I"  .daer ti ",nahoJ"
,neht ,ytilibissop fo sllih eht revo rednaw dluow sthguoht riehT
nruter dluow ehs nehw dna
.ti tlef ecno reven evah I hguoht
,egaugnal ydob fo eno ton ,sdrow fo eno ton
,yspit ylriaf eb dluow meht fo lla ,emit siht yB
.lla retfa ,flesmih tuoba ylknarf kaeps ot noisacco eht eb ton dluow sihT
.neH rehtoM dlO eht ta meht teem og ot
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.srehto ynam htiw ro ,rehtona htiw evil ot dennalp ro htiw devil yeht emoh kcab taht ,lacipyt ton saw
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.did syawla eh sa ,enola evirra dluow eH
,llew sa meht morf trap dluow eh dnA
,enoyna ,enoemos dnif ot etarepsed etiuq
.mih saw tI  .reh llet ot tnaw dluow eh ,reh t'nsaw tI
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
,lacipyt saw siht dnatsrednu ot hguone llew mih wonk ton did ohw esoht ni desuac siht yteixna eht llems ot nigeb dluow eh
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,dnatsrednu dluow wonk did eh mohw esoht
.etivni txen eht litnu
.evah ot demees enoyreve taht
.emit eht lla erongi t'ndluoc eh taht
,draneReL knarF yb
edistuo deppets eh dna
,rettam eht no kaeps ton dluow eh tuB
.thgil nruter taht ,emoc reven dluow ti tuB
--spahrep---fi neve ,stneve hcus ot mih etivni ot eunitnoc did
?etilopmi eb taht dluow ro
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
.gnirehtag laicos rehto yna ro ,sgnituo ,seitrap
.regnil ot gnol yrev tub esira ot neddus yrev
.syaw trap dluow devirra ohw esoht
,yletamitlU  .saw reven tI
.reh tuoba tnecs a teg dluow ehs ,noitasrevnoc siht gnirud tniop emos ta tuB
.shtnom rof morf gnippis neeb d'eh elttob yeksihw eht yb
.ria eht raelc ot ecnahc reporp eht teg dluow eh syad eseht fo eno
.gniht hcus on yas dluow eh tuB
.sreh fo epoh emos dehsad d'eh fi rednow dluow eH
,tesnus retfa tsuj thginoT
.reeuq tib a mih dnuof yeht-
,lla retfa laer eb tsum tI
.enoyna htiw yltnerruc ton saw ehs
,dna ,klat ot eunitnoc dluow yehT
,thguoht eh dna ,slrig gnisahc syawla saw ohw dneirf a dah eh ,pup a tsuj saw eh nehW
.edaf dluow thgil nwo reh erom eht ,kcab thgil a gnidnes mih tuohtiw og dluow noitasrevnoc eht regnol eht dna ,emoc reven dluow tI
”eérioS ehT“ saw sihT
?detcejer leef ehs diD
.tnemegagne reh no asilannA etalutargnoc niaga lla dluow yehT
dettimda ohw dna
eerf era elpoep reeuq erehw dlrow a rof elggurts eht ni
.laicos-itna ton saw eH  .egilbo dluow eH
:noitcejer a drah woh dnA
,snoitseuq ralimis reh ksa dluow eh ,od ot gniht etilop eht si ti esuaceb ,semitemoS
.ecneh sruoh wef a
.neht ,mih rof drawkwa leef dluow tI
.oot ,em rof ,yademos spahrep ,thguoht eh dna ,rentrap a dnuof ohw dneirf rehtona dah eh ,redlo werg eh nehW
,nettirw era selat dna gnus era sgnos hcihw fo ,tcnitsni siht ,evird sihT
,mih nihtiw duolc a pu derrits eton eht tuB
htiw saw eh eno eht fo
.mih ot kaeps ot nigeb dna
gniht yrassecen tsom eht spahrep si ytinummoC
.enola devirra ohw ,flow sihT
,tcejretni dluow eh ,dda ot gnihtemos dah eh fI
enola gnieb rieht taht ,elbissop sa yllacinagro sa ,hsilbatse ylkciuq dluow
.meht fo tsom saw hcihw
.su nioj ot detnaw uoy fi ,tesnus retfa tsuj neH rehtoM dlO eht ta eb ll'eW
,yhs yrev ylpmis eh saW
,sremotsuc rehto eht fo trofmoc eht rof duol oot tib a
,wohemos ,daetsni tub
.ti dellems eh wonk dluow yeht dnA
.retal tib a gnitarelecca ,tsrif ta ylwols ,ecnemmoc dluow gniknirD
.niaga eton eht ta decnalg nahoJ
,debekal a no liat sti gnippihw hsif a morf ekil tlis fo mossolb a
.gaw ot nageb liat sih dna ,slian krad prahs sih htiw potksed sih deppat eH
.dlrow siht otnu emac tsrif sevlow ecnis neeb evah dna
.ecnalg a mih eraps dluow meht fo enO
mih morf ssorca tis dna erutaerc laicos a sa ytud reh pu kcip dluow ,yrevarb lacimehc htiw deubmi won
,niaga ,nageb tI  draneReL
did ohw esoht dna
sucof rieht sa ,dnuorgkcab eht otni rehtruf tfird dluow ti ,sknird hguone fo liat eht tA
knarF yb ”eérioS ehT“
?snoitaler sih hsilbatse ton eh dluow yhW
,evah ot demees yeht taht gnihtemos gnikcal saw eH
.ton thgim yeht ro ,sevlesmeht ecudortni thgim t'ndid ohw esohT
.ti ezingocer ot emac eh taht yltnecer litnu t'nsaw ti tub
,spup evah ot nageb neve dna snoomyenoh no enog
.erom tey yteixna rieht esaercni dluow siht dna ,ksa ot drawkwa oot leef dluow yeht dna ,flesmih gniht a hcus hsilbatse reven dluow eh tuB  .etam ot ,nioj ot
dna deirram neeb dah ,srentrap dnuof yllanif dah sdneirf sih fo lla
eton a tsuJ  .etivni na htiw
?roivaheb reh fo raef fo tuo
.hguone doog eb dluow taht dna
.rekihhctih flowerew
.KU eht ni remonortsa na sa skrow stra eht ni gnigagne ton nehw ohw
.gnihsilbuP sirneF morf elbaliava si
,ysae syawla ton dna
rettu htiw tem saw
.ygoloib fo eno ,tnecs
deraeppa syawla hcihw serutcip gnivom fo sdnik eht was eh duolc taht nihtiw dnA
.gnikool saw ehs dias ehs dna ,enola emac ,oot ,ehS
taht noitazilaer taht htiw saw ti dnA
,citamotua ton si ti ot gnitcennoC .detpecca dna
?tseretni fo tuo ro ,ytip fo tuo mih ot emoc ehs diD
.noitcartta dellac gniht siht ,ecnamor dellac gniht siht ,lla retfa laer eb tsum ti esoppus I
tekcaj sih no tup eh
,srehto eht ot mih ecudortni ton dluow mih wenk ohw esohT
.netsil dna tnelis tis dluow eh ton fi tub
,stseretni sih tuoba ,krow sih tuoba ,flesmih tuoba snoitseuq mih ksa dluow ehS
.mih teerg dluow mih wenk ohw esohT
,srehto eht ekil ton saw eh dnatsrednu ot emac eh
.edur ylbarelotni demees evah tsum tI
.ylrae demossolb ohw eno si taht
.hguone tnasaelp ti dnif dluow ehS
?snoitaler neewteb eh saW
,seérios dekilsid eh taht t'nsaw tI
,eb tsum ti esuaceb ,si ytinummoc reeuq eht tub
,rettal eht did eh fI
.no raew dluow thgin ehT  .krow ,tnemniatretne ,scitiloP  .dnim
,relevart wollef ruoy
nehW  .noitarepsed rieht dnatsrednu ton did eh esuaceb
.ecnereffidni etelpmoc dna
eht fo edistuo ,dnah-ta saw noitasrevnoc revetahw ot detfihs
.meht rof evloser ton dluow ti os dna
.ria eht raelc ot evird eht teg dluow eh oS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
lla dna ,dne na ot emoc dluow thgin eht
.tuo saw eh elihw rood sih rednu dils
,suoedih saw ehs ebyaM  ?nosaer emos rof
srehto eht dna enibaS ,lla retfA
meht elosnoc ton dluoc eh dna
.setivni eseht fo tseheb eht ta
?detpmorp sselnu kaeps ot gnilliwnu os dna
?yag eb eh dluoc rO
,noisluver sa gnitadilav yldetsiwt os gnihtemos neve ton htiw tem saw
.nrut ni hcae meht rewsna dluow eh dna
"yellaV ylenoL eht ot yaW ehT" ,levon trohs siH
.flesmih ecudortni ton dluow eh dna
,draneReL knarF yb ”eérioS ehT“
,ksed sih no eton eht tes eH  .enibaS ,dengiS  ".su
.noitasrevnoc a evah dluow yehT  .esabegdelwonk nwo sih gnisu meht fo ffo draobgnirps ot yrt dna srewsna reh ta don dluow eh dna
?won detnioppasid leef ehs diD  ?remrof eht saw ti fi ,tseretni na etaerc thgim noitasrevnoc a pu gnikraps kniht ehs diD
,yltcerid mih ksa yeht dluohS
fo eno tub ,eltbus os esle gnihtyna ro ,ytilanosrep fo hsalc ro
.esle enoemos morf ssorca tis dluow ehs
:thguoht eh neht yllanif
,ehs os dna ,ecaps otni gnirats yllanoisacco ,gninetsil dna gnittis ylerem saw eh taht ees dluow ehS
demahsa saw eh spahrep rO
.dab leef t'ndeen ehs dna ,reh t'nsaw ti oS
,roivaheb sih tuoba suoixna leef thgim suht ohw ,wonk t'ndid ohw esoht eb syawla dluow ereht fi neve dnA
.neht ,mih tuoba kniht ot nigeb dluow yehT
,sevlesmeht ,enola devirra evah ton dluow yehT