.ytilaer fo srenroc eht ta
.deb ot tnew yeht ,eno yb eno dnA
,nwo sti detfil ti
.laer saw hcuot eht dnA
reh erofeb gniees dna
kcab kramkoob reh dednah araS
,kcor daed dna elap fo gnipporctuo ehT
,tserof eht ni owt htrow ton dnah eht ni drib a saw ,lla retfA
.tsigoloeahcra ehT
,htrae eht ot won dnuob
:railimaf dnoyeb erew ruf reh fo ssentfos eht ot tsartnoc tes taht ]ees·irb·iav[ eassirbiv ynit esoht dna
.erom ecno teiuq werg pmac ehT .tsal ton did tI
.did ehs taht wenk eduJ
,desnet dna dehcnuh dna deppots dah ehs taht
,ytilauq tsehgih eht fo rebma :enots-doG ehT
.reh fo tnorf ni saw ehs ereht dnA
.toor koot etoyoc eht
,revo ti dednah dna deggurhs eduJ ”?ti si tahW
,werg reh nihtiw thgil eht
,noitidepxe rieht fo rebmem htfif eht ,tsigoloeg eht retfa deksa ,tsiugnil s’maet eht sa devres ohw flow nacixeM yknal a
.ecafrus sti no srettel dehcte eht
.fles tcefrepmi yltcefrep reh
,pihsnoitaler
,lios eht drawot nwod dnah reh dediug yltneg dna
,niaga teem ew litnu dna ,sdleif ruoy no llaf niar eht yam ,ecaf ruoy no enihs nus eht yam ,uoy dniheb eb dniw eht yam
.erehwesle saw dnim reh sa ,mrof reh derussa tsael ta rO .reh derussa
,ooM ooM elbaffeni eht
,gnicap neeb dah ehs taht
,nehtgnel ot nageb dnuobnu suht dna ,dnuownu
,stniop enacra eseht neewteb seriw gnurts dah eh ecnO
.deliaf thgil ehT
.erom ecno degrevid sevitarran lanosrep nwo rieht dna stnet rieht ot detaerter yeht eno yb enO .tsinatob ehT
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,enots-doG eht dnuora delruc sregnif reh ,ereht dnA .sumuh dna
,tniop taht ta rof
.semit fo tseb eht ta nemo lli na si ohw
.s’flow eht tsniaga ylfeirb gnihsurb sregnif
.ssalc ygoloporhtna dargrednu na rof gnisselb elohw eht no repap a etorw dna elihw a rof segaugnal citleC deiduts I
.efil nwo sti tsiser ot demees
,eert wen eht eciton ot tsrif eht saw amup eht
.hcuot ot gniht A
.laer erew sesuollac eht dna mraw saw hcuot eht dna
,erehw gnipporctuo eht ediseb ereht
,regguR .P .B yb daer ,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
saw erehT .reh saw erehT
,tnet rieht fo tnorf ni hcae ,tas ruof ehT
.niap fo erusaem ehT .sey
,flesreh naht rehto ytitne emos
.syad owt tsal eht revo hsitef reh emoceb dah ti
,ti ekil gnihtemos ro ,ssarB
,gnipporctuo eht ekil ,tI
.taht htiw yalp tsuj neht dna koob ruoy fo segap owt ekil daer uoy ,pmac ta ereh er’ew emit yrevE .tahT“
.dennirg flow yddur ehT .deksa noraA
.thgirpu dekrej eduJ
,detrahcnu dna wen
dah eh ”,ereh reffid dluow thgil sa cisab sa gnihtemos kniht ot nosaer oN“
.swalc reh ot dekac trid eht saw erehT
,dnik ton ;elims ymaerd A
,os did ehs sa dnA
”.egde no elttil a em sah ecalp siht ebyaM .yrros ,haeY“
”doG fo dnaH ehT“ si yrots s’yadoT
.wonk t’nod I .ebyaM .oN“
,dnah taht fo thgiew eht tlef ehS
.demaerd srehto eht spahreP
.niap fo lenrek a si hcihw ni deddebme
,eveileb llits I .yas d’I
…dna seborts demit dna sesnel lacirehps dna snoitarreba citamorhc dna stnemerusaem gnibircsed ,boj sih gniod
,ecaf sti no derorrim saw noisufnoc ymaerd eht elihw dnA
,dekcut dna deltsirb liat ,ydaer ,tuaT
.haeY“ ”?ti wonk uoY“
.rettahc ot deunitnoc noraA
.wob a otni ydob reh demrof dna reh nekatrevo dah sseniraw laref raen A .dehcnuh rO
gut ot ohce yrotcaflo nA
.goD fO tsohG ehT dellac noitatneserp neewollaH laiceps a fo trap sa
.dnof leef ton did
,dna ,erutseg eht nruter ot nwo sti tuo dehcaer ti
.noisnet detacorpicernu ni deltsirb sreksihw reh ro
,ytisoiruc osla saw ereht
.rettam eht fo sdnah reh gnihsaw
”.sdnah yM fo smlap eht no uoy devargne evah I ,eeS“
,ssarb niht eht otni dehcte srettel eht tlef ehS .nettogrof koob
”.noisrev siht tog ew dna
dnats regnägleppoD reh was ehs ,ruf gnittilps
,dexaler yeht dnA
.meht hcuot ot tuo dehcaer sdnah ekil sdnorf dna ria eht deregnif snref erehw
,htrae morf pu yldilots gnibmilc skcor daed esoht erehw drawot gnivom reh ot
,ereh kciht os s’ria ehT .haey ,thgiR“
,egnahc elbisiv emos eb tsum ereht erus saw ehS
.gnihtemos draeh evah thgim uoy thguoht I“
,yvaeh saw ria eht dna
,yretsym yna ekil dnA .si
,enots eht no nettirw
,gniwonk ton ,leurc ton
,despal yltneg…hu ,m’I .haeY“
.gnihtyna leef ton diD
”?yako uoY“ .degnit-rrup
,tcaxeni revewoh
,pmac eht ot kcab yaw eht nO
,rorrim a ton saw tI .ecaf nwo reh
.sdrow on ,sdrow oN
,gnizeeuqs ,gnizeeuqs
,gnoleb ton did taht eert a fo edahs eht otni kcab deklaw yehT
,spahrep ,dnoces a flah yb ffo saw gnihtaerb riehT
.aera na dortnu os devom wodahs dna thgil yaw eht gnirusaem saw eH
.teiuq :pmac eht tA
,ykrans gnihtemos gniyas fo egde eht no saw ehs hguoht sa dekool tsiugnil ehT
,yrtemiroloD ?niaP
.tcaxe ton erew stnemevom eht rof
,drawyks hcra ot ,nehtgnerts ot
gnikaw neewteb noitisnart taht dessim dah ehs sa tsuj ,ti dessim ehs
”.gnihtemos enin-ytrof haiasI“
,erew yeht revetahw ,scisyhp sih gniod ,saw noraA ereH
.gnicaf neeb dah ehs yaw hcihw rebmemer t’ndid ehS
.gnihtyna rof gnihcraes erew uoy ekil t’nsaw tI
,sredluohs reh erauqs ,pu nethgiarts ot troffe suoicsnoc a htrof tup ehS .gninetsil
.tsrif rebmevoN tuo gnimoc
”.nezorf tsuj erew uoY
.shtnom wef tsal eseht won gniworg ,tserof gnidnuorrus sti dna
,ymaerd a tsuJ .tnarongi ton
.nihtiw deddebme niap fo lenrek a htiw rebma
,pmac ta kcab ,saw ehs ereh dna
]’rehtaf‘ ni sa ’a‘ tub ,’nu‘ hcnerF ekil ,dezilasaN * -  THAL rah-OB *a eer-YAN
.noitseuq a t’nsaw tI ”.cilohtaC er’uoY“
.thgin eht fo sdnuos eht morf edisa etulosba saw teiuq eht dna
,egami rorrim reh saw erehT .reh
.nehw fo erawa ton saw ehs tub
,tserof tnadnetta sti dna
.spahrep ,dleif-bus A
,tuo denut dah eduJ .sdnah syawlA
.dehcuorc neeb dah ehS
,dnah taht tlef eduJ ,denetsil ehs sa dnA
dehcuot spitregnif rieht dna rehto hcae drawot tuo dehcaer yeht dnA
,yaw egnarts emos ni ,gniswodnu
”.yrros ,haeY“ ”?yako uoY“
sdog fo gnikniht reh tog drow eht fo flah-tnorf eht nwod gnihgiew oeht taht dnA
doG ta gnitniop regnif a saw hcihw gnipporctuo eht yb ereht
,timda ot evah uoy tuB“
hug[ .tael rahtób na írié-n oG“ .denetfos ezag reh tub
.gnikool neeb dah tsinatob eht noitcerid eht ni seert eht otni tuo dereep ,denworf noraA ”.wonk
,gninetaerht dna gnitrofmoc ecno ta
.derebmemer gnihtemoS .nwonk gnihtemoS
?regnif taht fo renwo eht tA ?dnah
.dnal neila ylwen siht ni ereh tuo gniod erew yeht saw ti revetahw nahT ?krow
,thgim ehs sa deknilb ti elihw dna
.ton ro gnidaer ,ton ro gnikniht
yojne esaelP  kni.oykam ta
gnipporctuo suonimun eht yb ereht
.kniht I .senil lareves s’ti ,haeY“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
reh ton saw taht reh eht sa nekorb saw gnirorrim eht ,yllanif dnA
”–ereht revo gnikool detrats dna ezorf uoY
.knurt sti dnuora gnidniw wen dna egnarts setyhpipe
?esnes ekam taht seoD ?enots-doG ehT
.suoicerpimes gnihtemos fO
”.enog tsuj s’eH .wonk t’nod I“ ,detaeper
.thgilf rof noitaraperp ni fi sa
.daeh ypeels reh detfil annalE
.senots fo dnim ni reh tup eti- ehT
.sdap reh no sesuollac eht erew erehT
,peelsa llef ehs hcihw ta tniop emos neeb evah tsum ereht dna seye reh desolc dna dap pmac reh no yal ehS
.ehs saw ehS .ti ton saw ehS
,tpels yeht spahreP
,htrae eht otni nwod meht gid dna sregnif reh daerps tsum ehs taht neht wenk ehs dna ,pmad ylegnarts
eb ot desoppuS .hsirI
,gnisserac ,gnisserpmoc
,nus anozirA eht morf feiler kees dluoc yeht
,ereh saw ehS ?ehs saW
,daor ruoy no kcul doog‘ ,ekil s’tI
,stneirtun eht detsat dna
,teiuq saw eciov s’noraA
ria eht deregnif snref erehw
.tsinatob a sa ton ,sreh toN
.eta yehT .teiuq :neht dnA
,hU .eglieaG s’tI
,pirg ,eldarc ti tleF
.secnereffid eltbus erew erehT
.hcum oot fo yhs tsuj tis ,meht gnidnif no
ta…ta gnitniop nrut ni saw ehs taht hcus
.meht hcuot ot tuo dehcaer sdnah ekil sdnorf dna ria eht deregnif snref erehw ,seert eht dnoyeb kcab
,redrob taht dessorc ehs hcihw ta
,yllacificeps yrev
detacilpmoc…a dah eW .dad ym morf tfiG“
.gninetsil erew meht fo llA
dluow saw kniht dluoc eduJ lla dnA
,]nelots[ nolots a mra reh dna steltoor neeb evah tsum sevlesmeht swalc reh taht
,flesreh fo noisrev rehtonA
.dehsaba dekool eH .ecneliS .tnatsid
maol fo reyal eht htaeneb esahcrup dnuof dna
.seenk rieht ot nwod delttes htob yeht dna
.ti tuoba gnihtyna dias srehto eht fo enon tub
.gnipporctuo eht gnicaf erom ecno
.mraw saw tI .elbaplap saw tI
.ylimaerd delims noraA
,egap dehsinifnu eht revo pu detnet ,nwod koob reh tes neht dna ,segap wef a rof daer eduJ
.enog saw eduJ eciton ot tsrif eht saw anilevaj eht ,ekowa noraA nehw dnA .doG gnikees ,srats gnikees
.tfel I erofeb em ot siht evag eh tub
:lavorppa ruoy rof dettimbuS
,gnilbac eht gniodnU
.yvaeh werg ria ehT
”?gnihtemos raeh uoy diD .thgirla s’tI“
,saw ehs ereht dnA
,tserof eht fo egde eht nihtiw tsuj snoitpartnoc sseltnuoc pu gnittes ni dnah a anilevaj a gnivig etoyoc a htiw nageb yad ehT
.ti t’nsaw taht ,oN ?ssendaS
”?huh ,’uoy teem ot pu esir daor eht yaM‘“
,tnew eh sa no delttarp eH
.hguoht ,mih ecaf ot denrut dah ehs taht wonk did ehS
.doG drawot gnitniop
.erofeb morf erudecorp eritne eht dnuownu yeht neht dnA
,toor koot swalc reh htaeneb trid eht taht tlef ehs
.edilloc ton dluow yeht taht os nwo reh evoba mra sti devom
,ekowa annalE nehw dnA
,emoclewnu fo esnes krad emos htiw yawa ti dehsup
.elims elbativeni
.pmac drawot kcab ,dehsaba ,denruT
— ti fo tnecs eht dnA
.flesreh naht rehto gnihtemos sa regnägleppoD detnecs-maerd siht fo gnikniht deppots dah ehs dnA
.s’anilevaj eht toN
.ereht gnidnats tpek tsuj uoy neht tuB“
”.mM“ ”.negyxo hcum oot s’ereht ekil
,sthguoht-non dna sthguoht fo mrots eht hguorht ekorb sdrow s’annalE
,tlef nwo reh sa tfos sa saw ruf sti dnA
.tbuod a dnoyeb pihsnoitaler eht devorp taht yaw a ni nwonk
,oraugas dna sutcac lerrab eht yb kcab
.ydaerla wenk ehS
,ssendnof dehcated a osla
,tserof taht naht rehto efil detsiseR
,sdoow eht ni gnidnats reh ot tnet reh ni gnieb etoyoc eht morf noitisnart a neeb dah ereht fi dna
,flesti fo dna ni ,ti tahw ,snigeb ti woh ,morf emac ti erehw ton wonk ew ,yad yreve su htiw si ti hguohT
.sdnaH .sdnaH .ecneliS
.dnim reh dnuora esolc ,dnah s’doG tlef
,lios eht htaeneb delwarc sregnif reh dnA
,god.ecioveht ta
,deliaf dah thgil eht dna
?ti was I fi enots-doG eht wonk I
,dnatsrednu ton did ehs rof
.seliforp rieht fo lla wenK
.yretsym a si ti ,si efil esle revetahW
”doG fo dnaH ehT“ saw sihT
,skoob xis fo rohtua eht si ehS
tey dnA .gnipeels dna
.maerd a tsuJ
”.part tsiruot emos morf ylbaborp ,kramkoob a tsuJ
,dna ,stimil reh tset ti tleF .ezeeuqs ,nethgit
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gninetsil ,llat dekrep srae
,ecaf sti hcuot ot dnah reh tuo dehcaer ehs nehw dnA
.tuons sih htiw derutseg eH
.doG fo ,spahrep ,dna
,eseht dnA .fleseno fo
,mra reh pu delwarc krab eht sa neve dnA
,erofeb dah reven ti taht yaw a ni sesnes reh kcurts — flesreh fo
.elddim eht ni kcuts -lod- eht saw ti spahrep rO
”.egnarts elttil a s’gnihtyreve
.tcefrepmi saw edutitcaxe eht
?yad retfa yad revo deliot tsiugnil eht sdrow-flah deroloc-tsur eht erew
regnif tahT .eye eht werd tey dna
.sdap reh tsniaga seil gnillet sepahs eht tlef
,doots dah ehs taht dnif ot desirprus saw reh fo trap tnatsid emos dna
,dexaler ronaemed s’anilevaj eht ,taht tA
.etilodoeht eht fo krow eht
,sdor eht gnihtraenu
,ruf hguorht gnizarc skram-walc
.elihw a neeb s’tI
.degnahc eb ot si ti ssentiw ot
niaga seye reh gninepo fo erawa ylno saw ehS
,sa etarelecca htworg tlef ehs dnA .ytilibativeni tsuJ
,araS ,tniop eno tA
.srehto eht fo tifeneb eht rof
.feiler krats ni gniraelc eht tes stsop evif lla morf thgil neddus A .hsalf A
.kciht werg teiuq ehT …gnizeeuqs
,redael otcaf ed ,annalE dna
.ruf reh fo ssentfos eht saw erehT .tneserp saw tI
.secalp fo dednuorgnu tsom siht ni gnidnuorg gnihtemoS
,kramkoob eht ot derutseg araS ”?tahW“
.dnuorg eht evoba teef evif ereht dleh seirtemoeg enacra fo ten elbisivni na gnibircsed
?ecneics a taht saW
.reh rehtona saw tI
.nwo reh dnoyeb mrof rehtona morf did ti sa gnimoc
?etil-odoehT ?etilod-oehT .etilodoehT ]etil·hud·wa·eeht[ .’etilodoeht‘ drow eht retfa kcart tsol ylegral ehS
.kramkoob reh saw taht latem fo mihs niht eht daetsni deregnif dna
”.wonk t’nod I .ebyaM .oN“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,mets-niarb reh tsniaga erom ecno elttes
,laref ,rehto hcae drawot dehcuorc yeht dnA
,tcerrocni eb ot won nevorp ,ereht sdrow eht tlef
dnim reh dnuora pirg sti denesool dah doG fo dnah ehT
.yltsoc ton tub ,ytterP
”.sseug I ,wonk uoy tahw etirW
.gaw a ta tpmetta nA .xaler meht tel
.demaerd yeht spahreP .ton spahrep
,ti tlef ehs sa ti wenk ehs ,deedni dna
?ton yeht erew ,nwo reh erew sdnah reh dnA .ehs saw ehS
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”doG fo dnaH ehT“   .goD fo tsohG eht …no thginot ,doG fo dnaH ehT
.reh ot elims dna
.meht hcuot ot tuo dehcaer sdnah ekil sdnorf dna
”?yawyna ,taht si tahW“
.gnikam rieht ni dnah a dah ehS
”.ereht ti ekil t’nod I
”?’gnisselb elohw ehT‘“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,tcaxeni erew ,oot
naht…naht rehto gnihtyna tuoba sruoh ni nekops dah meht fo yna tsom eht saw tI
”.dekrow taht doG knahT“
,dnatsrednu ot epoh reven dluoc eduJ ligis a gnibircsed
,traeH eht fo ssendliW A ,tsetal reh htiw
,gniod saw eh tahw gnibircsed
,daeh reh detfil ehs nehw dna
,gnidnatsrednu na
.eb tsum ehS ?peelsa ehs saw
.tsiugnil ehT .tsicisyhp ehT
.dnim delttesnu reh revo delttes teknalb a sa reh morf gniniard noisnet eht ,denworf etoyoc ehT
,oga sega noitalsnart eht pu dessem enoemos tub ,’lufsseccus eb slevart ruoy yam‘
,ymaol ylegnarts ,ekiltresednu
,denepeed ssenkrad eht sa neve taht tlef eduJ dna
taht fo renwo eht tA ?tahw
,ti deregnif ehs dna
.gniyrrac saw ehs tnempiuqe tahw ,gnisu saw eh sloot tahw
,eert emos rof rennur eht saw ydob elohw reh taht
.ssam ot og t’nod tsuj
.seirots neewollaH gnidaer er’ew keew siht dna
,neht ,tnemetats A
,wol eciov s’amup eht
gnitirw reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna kni.oykam.ssendliw
?od dluoc noitcelfer a taht gnihtemos taht saW
,denesool selcsum reh dna doow emaceb senob reh
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,ereht retaw eht fo knard dna
”.gnipporctuo eht ot revo–“
.gnixaler selkceh
“’.dnah siH fo mlap eht ni uoy dloh doG yam
.oykam.ssendliw ta erom tuo dnif nac uoY
”.yeH“ ?ti dehcuot I fI
.tnempiuqe eht decalp anilevaj eht elihw noitats latot eht deggul etoyoc ehT
.noisneherpmoc dna yduts detsiser taht kcor ehT
.ynegoehT .ygoloehT
tsirw reh revo pu sregnif reh dils
sdnah reh no doolb htiw dnah ni dnah decrof saw dnah reH