,sgel wolley-ylacs ,dewalc no drawpu delbbarcs anoiF
erom emos koob eht esworb d’ehs
.koob eht ni egaugnal eht fo reh dednimer taht ytilauq lacisum a dna tnecca lacol a dah tI
,mra reh ta nwod dekool anoiF
.thgiew sih rednu reh gnihsurc tneverp ot swoble sih no gnitser
.shgiht reh nwod ,spih reh
riah ylruc sih ni delgnat neht dna
,gnilworg etiuq ton ,desnet ehS
tfahs reh no gnikcus
liated tseinit eht tuo kcip dluoc seye reH
,drawrof reh dellup eH
,dnah sih fo evaw a htiW
,yks eht ni kceps a tsuj ,mih ees dluoc ehs dna
.trihs etihw tfos dna
.skooB selaT dnuoB yb secapS railim-ruF dna
,dehsinif yllanif ehs nehW
.thgiew reh troppus ot elbanu erew sgel reh
,namuh a ekil kcen eht fo pot eht ta gnidne fo daetsni ,taht was ehs
,ylleb reh hguorht amgam ekil saw hcuot siH
.sruof lla no gnihsad semitemos
,niaga ecno htooms
.hcum erac ot mees t’ndid niol reh tuohguorht sgnileef wen-dnarb eht tub
.mih rof sgel reh gnidaerps ,revo tneb ehs
.skao dlo fo lufdnah a neewteb ecaps eht ni reh hctac ot mih dewolla dna
,sekorts dipar ,gnol ni
.stsaeb fo gnik-eaf dna neeuq eht ekil
.deifinosrep ecarg saw ehS
.rehtruf ecnartne reh gnihcterts
,gnineppah saw tahw dezilaer ehs erofeB
.htuom sih otni sinep reh koot ,drow a tuohtiw
,reh dnuora lla epacsdnal eht ta derats ehs sa epaga htuom reh
.emoc reh ni ylleb reh dna eert eht gnirevoc ,demsagro ehs
,ssik eht otni delims eireaf ehT
spih eht hguorht rethgit hcum
htap emos gnola reh gnihsup reh fo edisni sregnif sih
,tfahs reh revo eugnot sih nar eh elihw
.spil sih yb delffum ylthgils ylno maercs reh
.gnol os gnittauqs morf dna dloc eht morf ,truh ehs dna
,tsiaw dna spih reh desserac sdnah hguor siH
,tcere yllufniap selppin
dekool eh naht regnorts hcum saw eH
sirotilc reh revo nwod dils bmuht siH
ruf ynwat ,krad ni derevoc ,sevooh nevolc
,tsrif teef reh ot teg ot deganam anoiF
.yssup reh otni regnif a dils eh sa dehcra anoiF
,teknalb eht no tuo dial llits sgnireffo reh fo stnanmer eht
.dnuom revo gnibbur llits dnah sih fo mlap eht
esab eht dnuora delaes spil sih gnipeek
,nosirroM .A ylloH yb
daeh reh koohs neht
.emit gnol a tnelis saw eH
ssik eht ekorb ehS
ecar traeh reh gnikam
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.ylleb reh otni htmraw gnillips
,reh revo nwod dehsarc
,htuom sih fo tuo llup reh tel yllanif eh nehW
.emit eritne eht tsehc sih ot ylrednet reh gnidloh eireaf eht
,nwod redluohs eht morf ,smra reH
.tsiaw reh dnuora derehtils mra eerf sih elihw
.retal tnemom a dexamilc dna
,reh otni tcarter ot gniyrt sinep
,dnopser ot detrats ehS
,pu tas eireaf ehT
.potniatnuom eht dnuora gnilcric
.edam eb ot sniagrab gnitseretni
,kcab gnillac htaerb etsaw ot rehtob t’ndid ehS
,elihw a rof noitseuq eht tuoba thguoht ehS
gnidda hteet prahs ylgnisirprus
.ksud ta lautir eht nigeb ot dias
dluoc ehs tseb sa mih dnuora nwod depmalc ehS
”,niagrab eht ot eerga I“
,elbatrofmoc ylesicerp t’nsaw tI
.dah yksihw eht ekil ydob reh hguorht htmraw gnidaerps
”acwP ehT“ saw sihT
,tnemom a rof doots ehS
,s’eireaf eht htiw deknil
,nam a no nees d’ehs yna naht rekciht saw sgel esoht neewteb gnuh taht sinep eht dna
.fo demaerd reven dah ehs noitamrofni fo htped a reh dedroffa
gniraelc eht otni deppets eh litnu
,yenoh fo raj a tnew taht potA
.daeh tnulb a htiw
,kcab dellup eh sa
,dekan ,doots ehs yhw fo trap saw hcihw
,tigid sih delggirw eH
,reh otni dils eh sa denaom ehS
.rewol gninrub sepoh reh dna eldnac eht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,hcamots dna kcab reh revo gnisaet
,taog niatnuom taerg a neve
.dniw niatnuom eht fo llihc tsal eht yawa gninrub
,deifingid dna duorp gniraeb reh
,wols a ot yaw evag noitarolpxe eht tniop emos ta taht dna
,enips reh pu deliart pitregnif yvaeh a
.tuo gnikcalb tuoba deirrow ehs taht esnetni os
,gel reh gnitfil sdnah sih fo eno
,thgir nwo reh ni nexiv a
,ytniad no doots eh daetsnI
,reh desaet eh gnol woh erus t’nsaw anoiF
.eert eht ot dennip flesreh dnuof ehs dna
.mih fo kcart gnipeek elbuort dah anoiF dna
,pu dekool ehs ,ylsuovreN
.tekcor a ekil drawpu tohs dna
.yawa dehtooms hselfesoog reh dna
,seot dna sregnif reh fo spit eht ot gnidaerps
,denaom dna kcab denael ehS
egassap eht fo dne eht dehcaer anoiF .kcen reh gnola
,tnemssarrabme reh oT
sdnuos dnasuoht a reh gnignirb
teef reh ot reh dellup dah eh erofeb htuom reh fo tuo ylerab erew sdrow ehT
.ssendloc tnatsid a saw ti tub
,mih tsniaga pu flesreh derevel ehs dna
,kcen sih dnuora depparw smra reH
.mih retfa yks eht hguorht esor dna
,nwod dettauqs ehS
.noitom diulf ,eno ni ecarbme sih otni dna
dehsinif ehs retfa pu deps eireaf ehT
,reh derolpxe regnif sih sa
.deggurhs eireaf eht ,hgis a htiW
eligarf os dekool tI
,oot ,eireaf eht llems dluoc ehs dnA
.troppus rof tsniaga denael ehs hcihw ,hcrib a
.sredluohs reh gnola resool trihs reh dna
.eciov yrd ,tfos a emac
”,uoy sesaelp ti fi ,uoy esahc ot ekil dluow I“
reh fo edisni stnemevom llams sih fo hcae dna
.nwod kcab devid neht
eveileb I nehT“ .deddon ehS
smra sih otni reh dellup eH
ssik eht fo tuo dellup ehS
,eireaf eht retfa deps ehs sa
,ysae eb dluohs taht retfa gnihtyrevE
,demsagro ehs sa tuo deirc ehs dna
htuom sih otni denaom ehS
.gnitacixotni dna teews htaerb sih
.sevruc fo daetsni senil thgiarts lla ,llat oot flesreh thguoht ehS
,teknalb eht ot reh deirrac dna teef reh ffo reh tpews eireaf ehT
reh ot noitasnes wen yllohw a saw tI
.eugnot sih htiw htuom reh erolpxe mih tel ehs emit siht dna
.hgiht reh gnola pu gnidils sdnah nwo sih fo eno
.tsrif dehsinif eireaf ehT .tnemtnetnoc dna
,niaga reh ssik ot nwod denael eh
eoteltsim suonosiop eht koot eh sa
.htaerb peed a koot ehS
,dloc llits saw ehS
tserof eht hguorht edis-yb-edis deklaw tub
gnirevihs deppots ehS
kcab sih ta dewalc slianregnif reH
.reh otni denael eh sa sretemitnec wef a kcab reh gnitfil
gnilpuoc rieht fo sdnuos ehT
.erofeb decneirepxe reven dah ehs stnecs dna
erugif dennat ,llat a
thgir etiuq pu denil t’nsaw tI
,ylecreif mih dessik dna
.laciryl erew sdrow eht dna ,decitcarp dah ehs tub
,gnissik erew yeht dna
.rrup yrd-retniw a ni deksa eh ”?ydaer uoy erA“
”.trohs sworg emit ruO“
.dekcol spil ,rehto hcae dnuora depparw
.lio eht rof gnihcaer
”,nuS eht fo rethguaD ,derewsna evah I dna dellac evah uoY“
,taf fo ecart a tuohtiw drah
.htuom sih otni gnitsurht
nwad fo sregnif knip ,elap tsrif eht dna
”?pots ot em hsiw uoy oD“
,reh htaenrednu dils sdnah egral sih fo enO
,dehsinav ylpmis eh ro peelsa llef ehs rehtehw erus ton saw ehS
serutaef hguor htiw
,koob eht ni srettel tneicna eht decart sregnif reH
”.taht rof ksa t’ndid I“
sevooh eniuqe dilos eht erew enoG
.reh hguorht revihs ot tnemeticxe fo sevaw desuac taht spin elttil
.xes reh revo gnilkcit
.sbmil reh otni tuo gnidoolf
.stsaerb llams reh rednu dessorc smra reh htiw ria gnineve yllihc eht ni gnirevihs
,seert krad pu gnilbmarcs selteeb raeh dluoc ehS
.saw ehs htaerb fo tuo woh ta desirprus saw ehS
,tsiaw reh dnuora dils dnah eerf-won sih dna
.sbmil reh gnola denrub ti dna erif diuqil saw hcuot siH
,renwo s’eciov eht tuo ekam tsuj dluoc anoiF
skcor fo seires a gnola gnippoh
ysatsce ni delwoh neht
erew snaej reh taht dnif ot dethgiled dna dekcohs htob saw ehs tub
deeps pu gnikcip neht tsrif ta wols
erom pu tliub yeht sa mih tsniaga reh gnisserp
.reh fo edisni dehsup tigid kcils-lio eht sa htaerb a tuo dessih ehS
,kcalb ni deppit sgniw gnipeews eguh
,reh woleb tuo denepo dlrow ehT
.gniraelc eht edistuo tsuj gnidnats
,dehsinif eh nehW
.eireaf eht sa ecnarudne hcum sa htiw enoyna htiw neeb reven d’ehS
,ssenkrad eht otni gnitniuqS
,gnol oot ton retfa owt tsrif eht denioj regnif driht a taht ylno
,sevren reh gnola gnas ssenwen sti dna
.nus gnittes eht dna noziroh nretsew eht sdrawot gnicnalg
,oot ,neht sevooh neeb evah yam sdnah reH
.krims tnahpmuirt a htiw
,dnuorg eht otno rehtegot llef yehT
sserP lesaeW yb sliveD htiw gnicnaD
,deeps artxe fo tsrub a no tup dna dennirg anoiF
,detaes llits meht dnif ot seye reh denepo ehS
,dia na naht noitcartsid a erom saw dnah sih dna
,hcamots reh revo dnah a nar ehS
,dna ,spih reh no sdnah sih gnicalp
”?rethguaD O ,kees uoy od tahW“
.anigav reh ot pit sti dediug eh sa drah ydaerla sinep sih
reh ni flesmih detlih eH
,yawa denrut neht
reh dehsup eH .reh hguorht tlob gninthgil a ekil saw tsurht hcaE
.snisuoc latrom rieht ot netsil llits thgim klof riaf eht taht
,esolc reh dleh eireaf ehT
ti morf eid thgim ehs thguoht ehs erup os erusaelp a dna
,sniatnuom yerg dna neerg fo tam gnillor a
.xaler ot tseb reh did dna
.tuo derettups yllanif eldnac eht litnu
,seirreb eoteltsim htiw dellif nikpan a
,ecnartne regae dna tew reh tsap dils tfahs tnulb siH
,thgiew dna htmraw gnitrofmoc sih rednu ,ereht yal ehS
sredluohs daorb sih revo decart sdnah reH
,emac eh sa mih ot gnulc anoiF
.reh dniheb dils eireaf eht
.enam delgnat ,gnol dna
”.neht ,ytuaeb tnereffid a uoy wohs llahs I“
noisnet gnikaerB
.sredluohs sih ot llef taht enam ylruc ,delgnat A
edisniatnuom yggarc eht hguorht dniw fo eltsihw eht rof tpecxe reh tcartsid ot gnihton saw erehT
,sgel reh daerps ylrednet eh sa xelf selcsum sih gnileef
.ecaf sih gnihctaw ,teknalb eht tsniaga kcab yal dna
,htym fo tuo yprah a ekil dekool ehS
,gnineppah saw tahw ssecorp dluoc ehs erofeB
.llits modeerf suoirolg
taht leef dluoc ehs tub
.kcab dloh ot deirt ehs sa pil rewol reh gnitib
,mih tsniaga reh dleh eH
.naom a delfits ehs dna
.nwod kcab gnilttes erofeb ,deganam ehs ”,uoy knahT“
.erofeb tlef reve d’ehs gnihton ekil
,pu gnirps liat nwo reh tlef ehS
.teef reh no reh tes dna eerf dnah sih dellup eh
.hcamots sih tsniaga leets fo dor a sinep reh
,reh gnisuffus erusaelp ehT
,hselfesoog ni derevoC
.yas ot tahw anoiF dlot dah koob ehT
,tsehc daorb sih otni denael ehS
evod dna deleehw ehs sa reh dnuora gnippihw dniw dloc eht
,ti desserac yltneg eH
,decnuop ehs nehw yawa egdod ot elbanu saw dna
”.niagrab eht delaes uoY“ .dehsulf ehS
.sih ot spil reh gnisserp
.ecaf yesroh sih no elims a htiw reh dlot eh
,teef dna sgel reh fo epahs namuh eht fo
.tfahs reh fo hcni yreve gnirolpxe eugnot
,ytrid dna deniats-dum saw hcihw ,toof reh fo pot eht gnola dna
,sih tsniaga spih reh dekcor ehs ,daetsnI
,erofeb decneirepxe reven dah ehs dlrow eht fo weiv a reh evag elzzum gnol a no ediw tes seyE
.eno yb eno ,meht tae ot nageb dna
,swap ot gninrut teef dna sdnah reh
,htuom reh morf dewolf yehT
”.ecarg rof deksa uoy
.htuom gnitivni reh otni gnippils eugnot sih
,xof lamron yltcefrep ,laer a tub
.yrt yllaer ehs did ron
,htaerb reh deniager anoiF erofeb dessap setunim lareveS .pu sgel reh werd ehs sa lruc seot reh gnikam
.meht dniheb pu emac nus eht sa seert eht hguorht noissecorp yletats a dael yeht ,mra-ni-mrA
,teknalb eht no nwod reh delttes eH
.yllacizziuq reh ta nwod dekool eH
,eson daorb ,gnol a dna
.aes tnatsid eht dna sekal gniremmihs
,pirg sih otni delttes dna ylduol denaom anoiF .reh otni kcab gnignulp neht dna
.reh otni rehtraf gnihsup erofeb htrig sih ot tsujda reh tel eireaf ehT
,reh dnuora deklaw eh sA
.niagrab a fo gnikirts lautca eht
”.niagrab a ekam ot tnaw I“
.reh dnuora tserof eht ni sevael der dna nworb fo eltsur eht dna
.dnoces a dedda neht
,dnuorg ymaol eht ot delbmut yeht dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.neeb dah liat a erehw ecnesba suoiruc eht neve
,reh retfa gnisahc mih draeh ehS
tahT“ .niaga thgiew reh troppus ot dediced seenk reh litnu ydaets reh dleh dna
,nosirroM .A ylloH yb ”acwP ehT“
,reh otni gnidils
”,nuS eht fo rethguaD O ,erusaelp a saw tI“
.derumrum eireaf eht ”,ytuaeB“
,edis eht ot detfihs eH
,hcamots reh fo tip eht ni eralf htmraw a tlef ehs
.niks reh fo tuo pael thgim ehs thguoht ehs dna
.kcapkcab reh ffo deggurhs ehs
,dias ehs ”,ecarG“ .nuf neve
.nwod reh tes ylluferac neht
”?ydaets niaga uoy erA“
,espoc llams a saw skcor eht fo pot eht tA
,elzzum derruf-kcalb
,ssenkrad eht otni rehtruf gab dna sehtolc reh devohs ehS
,reh revo denael eireaf ehT
si yrots s’yadoT dna
daeh sih debbob eH
dekan reh ssorca delbmuts dah erus saw ehs rekih eht rof tserof krad eht gninnacs
.mih ot ytuaeb deggur a dah eh tub
.deeps pu dekcip ehs sa
despalloc yeht erofeb potniatnuom eht gnola gnicnuob
.tsehc sih revo depparw sgniw yrehtaef reh
,tpecxe noitome rehto lla tuo dedworc dna
.esroh a ekil slipup latnoziroh htiw
,kcab s’eireaf eht dniheb sgel reh dessorc anoiF
,kcab reh no dnuorg dloc eht fo erawa saw ehs
srae gnileviws ,gnol dna eson wen reh tub
.eldnac xawseeb a dna
,oot ,saw ehs taht dezilaer ehs neht dna
,krab ekil-repap ,looc eht tsniaga ecaf reh gniyal
eroc reh hguorht daerps htmraW .deeps erom dna
,eltneg saw hcuot siH
,elddim reh dnuora pirg sih denethgit eh dna
,yssup reh tsniaga desserp neht
koob eht gnisolc fo egrev eht no saw ehS
.dnuorg eht no teknalb loow deydnu eht tuo daerps ehs sa
.shgiht derehtaef nworb morf gnigreme
,dnuorg eht dehcuot teef reh nehw tuo gnillup
,kcab reh revo gniruop lio eht tlef ehs neht dna gut a saw erehT
,daeh sih detlit eH
,knirhs mih dehctaw ehs sa deppots tub
.ria eht ta deplug ehs sa mih no nael reh tel eH
,emac ehs sa mih ot esolc reh dleh eH
eciov reh saw dnuos ylno ehT .derrits gnihtoN
,krow thgim koob siht taht ,thguoht hsiloof a neeb dah tI
moor letoh reh ot kcab ekih gnol eht nageb dna
,sgel reh neewteb
.ydob reh gnikcarw erusaelp
.meht gnilcricne srehtaef detlom fo gnir a
.stsaerb reh fo eno no gnitser erofeb edis reh gnola dna
.noom eht fo thgil thgirb ylegnarts eht dna
,evitcartta yllanoitnevnoc llac dluow ehs tahw ton saw ecaf siH
.yks nepo otni dna espoc eht fo tuo reh gniyrrac
.tserof eht hguorht deps dna denrut
.hctac htaerb reh dna
.niatnuom a fo edis eht no
.detnarraw yks krad eht ni gnuh taht tnecserc niht eht naht rethgirb
.lufrewop dna gnorts ydob reh
thgit reh dleh eireaf ehT
,edis reh yb tlenk eH
.smra ralucsum s’eireaf eht revo sdnah reh gninnur
flesreh dnuof ehs dna
,hguoht ,reverof tsiser t’ndluoc ehS
rehto yna erew ereht fi ees dna
eert eht ot resolc
ydaets reh dleh eireaf ehT
,niks reh gnisserac
,loow fo sserd tuc wol ylsuoladnacs a ni depard saw ehS
”,llew ecirp eht diap evah uoY“
,reh revo dils ssenthgit gnipeerc A
.stnemevom sih htiw etatsorp reh tsniaga debbur tfahs tnulb sih neht dna
.yleritne dnuorg eht gnivael
.lio elbategev eht htiw delddif eh elihw
mosob reh fo dnuom eht gnirolpxe sregnif
,sdnah nezorf ekil ydob reh revo decar tI
,sruof lla no yltfos dednal ehs neht dna
,reh no nwod dehsarc xamilc reH
niaga dnuorg eht tfel teef reh sa delaeuqs anoiF
.naom tfos a gniticile
,reh fo edisni eguh os tlef tI
.gnihcuot saw eh saw ti tahw dezilaer ehs erofeb dnah sih otni flesreh gnidnirg
odnecserc a dehcaer snoitasnes eht
.pot eht raen garc ylenol a ni gnidne
.dnuof eb ot erehwon saw eireaf eht dna
.stsaeb fo rennam lla fo liart eht kcart dna
,gniregnil a reh gnivig
”.ytingid dna ,ytuaeb“
.tsrif eht denioj regnif dnoces a dna
,ylitnuaj gniltsihW
.lufniap saw gnitiaw ehT
,resolc deldis eh sa deksa eh
gnineppah saw tahw ezilaer t’ndid ehS
,gniraelc eht otni deppets yeht sa
dnah sih fo mlap hguor eht htiw xes reh gnibbur demuser eH
”.tnemtcane sti ylno
dehgual eireaf ehT
eireaf eht revo gnidnats
.ssenregae dna noitapicitna htiw kciuq htaerb reh
.delbmum anoiF ”,gnizama saw
.raer sih morf gnituorps liat yhsub a
,dna nwod meht deppans dna
htuom dna dnah sih sa
,tuo deuaetalp stsurht rieht sa mih ot reh deldarc eH
,dezilaer ehs ,reed a saw eH
.deen dluow ehs reh dlot dah koob eht slairetam eht gab reh morf detacirtxe anoiF
,laeuqs reh gnikam
riah reh ta deggut tI
.nus tnecsan eht fo hcuot eht ta yawa denrub hcihw
yawflah tuoba tuo gnillup ,devom eh nehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
sreh no erew spil siH
.ti gnola decnad eugnot sih elihw
.remraw yna gnitteg t’nsaw ylniatrec ehs dna gnitanitsarcorp ot tniop on saw erehT .dehgis ehS
.egrahc ekat mih gnittel
.petstoof a draeh ehs nehw
.oot ,degnahc dah eH .dias eireaf eht
,reh gnidloh elbuort on dah dna
,noziroh eht gniraen saw noom ehT
trats ot suoixna saw anoiF
,sgniw otni demrofsnart neeb dah
,reh no kcus ot detrats eh litnu mih ta delggog ehS
,drawrof dehsup eH
,dezilaer ehs ,ydob reh dekcarw srevihS .desuap dna
,reh tsniaga pu dehsup saw regnif tnulb ,kciht A
ssenkrad eht ni yltbus detfihs erugif ehT
.sgniw kcalb yssolg ,tnaig erew yeht
.ffo gnirepat erofeb kcab reppu sih ot nwod deunitnoc riah sih
.koob eht dnif ot neeb dah ehs ykcul woH
,gnuoy dna htooms saw niks reh taht tpecxe
.niaga ecno ,anigav a ton ,sinep reh gnippuc saw eireaf ehT
,kcapkcab eht ni smeti rehto eht lla htiw ni dekcut ,koob ehT
.ti gnicart tigid hguor
.nedrah ot ti gnigaruocne
dnuorg eht raen oot deyarts eireaf ehT
,elttil a eert eht gnola nwod gnitoocS
,ecnatsid eht ni sthgil gnilkniwt fo sespmilg thguac ehS
,yltneg nwod reh tel eH
,seye reh denepo ehs nehw tub
,tsiaw sih dnuora sgel reh depparw ehs dna ,reh detfil eH
.hcrib eht tsniaga bur ot tfahs nwo reh desuac stnemevom sih fo eno yreve neht dna
.eldnac eht fo emalf der eht gnirrits
reh htaenrednu morf tuo dils dnah siH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.dluoc yeht sa tsaf sa gniog meht fo htob eht
:ssap meht dehctaw dna deppots slamina rehtO
sevooh kcalb kciht ni dedne sgel sih taht tpecxe ,gnikool namuh yldaorb saw eH .resolc emac eH
,eert tseraen eht ot revo reh dediug eH
,yksihw eht knard eh nehW
.spih reh debbarg eireaf eht sa derevihs anoiF
.elppin reh dnuof bmuht sih litnu
.txen saw yenoh ehT
,erofeb reh fo edisni gib os gnihtyna dah reven dah ehS
.senob reh ni peed ecarg a
,egnaro dna dlog denrub reh woleb ekal enipla eht dna
.ydob elohw sih revo tpews taht
.hguone esolc saw ti tub ,noitpircsed s’koob eht morf gnitcepxe neeb dah ehs tahw yltcaxe ton saw sihT
,niaga reh otni gnitsurht nageb eh sa
,degnahc dlrow elohw reH
.niaga reh ssik ot ni denael eh ,gninraw tuohtiW
.wols dna eltneg saw eh tub
.kcab degnahc dah yeht nehw fo erusnu
,teknalb eht no kcab yal ehS
.gnimlehwrevo emaceb ylkciuq snoitasnes eht tub
,niatnuom eht dessorcssirc taht esahc a no reh dael eH
.dessap yeht sa daeh denroh ,evissam sti dewob hcihw
.ssalg ekil ti rettahs thgim eciov reh thguoht drusba eht dah anoiF taht
,dedisbus xamilc reh litnu
.doots neht ,reh desaeler eH
tlik kcalb dilos a erow eh elihw
.ediw oot sredluohs reh ,worran oot erew spih reH
noitaticer htruof reh dehsinif ehS
noitceffa fo tnerrucrednu gnorts a ,spahrep
yltbus detfihs eireaf ehT
,htaerb reh niager ot detpmetta anoiF elihW
,tsehc sih gnola desaet sdnah reH .ssik peed
ruf kcalb dilos eht rof tpecxe
.noisiv reh fo tuo dna ni edils ot demees eH
.ecnartne reh ot tfahs sih ediug ot
.yks eht fo egde etisoppo eht gnola gnihcni erew
?dekrow evah ylbissop ti dluoC
,taorht reh fo enil eht gnola dessik dna nwod daeh sih dekcut eH
desolc tfird seye reh tel ehS
,nworb diuqil dna egral erew yehT
,redluohs reh otni gud kcapkcab reH
.ssarg remmus ekil llems teews ,toh a
,gnol a otni gnidnapxe ecaf sih
.ruf ,rethgil tiebla ,emas eht ni derevoc
.eireaf eht dnuora smra reh peek ot htgnerts eht dah ylerab ehs
,sgel reh neewteb dna dnuora dils dnah s’eireaf ehT
.ecnartne reh dnuof ti litnu ssa reh dnuora gnidils
,emit siht rehto hcae esahc t’ndid yehT
,deraelc msagro reh fo gof eht nehW
,emit siht naom eht elfits t’ndluoc ehS
.reve sa drah sa llits tfahs sih
.niaga flesreh dlot anoiF ,hsiloof saw sihT
.eldnac eht til neht
nirg a otni detfihs erats dehtuom-ediw reH
.llew a ekil seye eht dna
.tuo thgilnus lluf erew ti hguoht sa
,reh fo edisni dexelf tfahs kciht sih sa ylpeed denaorg dna
.kcab reh gnola gnikorts dnah eno
.draeh ylecracs ehs hguoht ,reh dlot eh
,reh hguorht erusaelp fo evaw a gnidnes
.nwonk reven dah ehs
.erom elims mih edam hcihw ,htuom sih otni esnesnon derumrum ehs dna
.mih tsniaga mriuqs ot reh desuac
,rehtegot devom yehT
,teknalb eht dnuora latem on saw ereht erus gnikam
,retto gnikool-dilos a
,swalc reh fo spit eht no pu doots ehs dna
pih reh tfel sdnah sih fo enO
,erutaerc namuh-flah a toN .xof a otni
esirprus ni depsag anoiF
”?tsoc eht wonk uoy oD“ .eh dias
nosirroM ylloH yb
.elbaroxeni tub ,rednet neve
,mih tsniaga bur ot ti desuac
.ekaw sti ni revihs a gnivael
.llits saw tserof eht dna ,deid dniw ehT
,deklaw ehs sa thguoht ehs ,ebyaM
.ssik eht otni kcab mih dellup dna
,namuh a sa reh deimyts evah dluow taht skcor delbmut revo delbmarcs ehS
,ekortsnwod eht dna hcaer sih fo thgieh eht neewteb erehwemos
,elip eht denioj ti rednu nrow dah ehs trihs-t knip eht dna retaews reH
,noitelpmoc s’niagrab eht fo trap toN“ .reh dlot eh
.deedni ,ytuaeb fo dnik tnereffid A
,tuo deirc ehs dna
.seitnap ycal dna
.selcsum railimafnu htiw
reh ta pu gnilkniwt seye
,neeb dah ruf reh roloc emas eht
,tsurht ot nageb neht
.psarg sih ni deredduhs ehs elihw
.lla ta gnivom eb ot mees t’ndid nus eht dna
,ti revo dekcilf eh sa deredduhs ehS
,yaw eno naht erom ni desopxe gnileef
.oot ,taht reh dlot dah koob ehT ”.od I“
.egde eht revo reh dehsup tfahs kciht dna
.rae reh otni derumrum eh ”,ytingiD“
,ria eht tpews sgniw s’anoiF
.koob eht morf daer anoiF
.thgilnoom eht ni gnitnahc dna
.gnitserra erew seye siH
,tuoba denraw dah koob eht tahw saw sihT
reh fo tiucric sih detelpmoc eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,gel reh revo dnah a nar ehS
,deretaw seye reh litnu ti dehctaw ehS
.seert eht neewteb gniohce
.tsurht hcae htiw sih fo ffo decnuob spih reh litnu
,hguoht ,gnikil reh rof noos oot raF .gninotsip ydaets
.reh tfel reven seye s’eireaf ehT
.tcere emaceb ehs sa
.revlis ekil sreltna fo ffo gnitnilg thgilrats tnatsid
– !liat a dah ehs – liat reh dekcilf ehS
.ediw reh gnidaerps
,hcum ydob reh ekil t’ndid anoiF
slarips ni pu sevael daed delriws dna
.tsap evod eireaf eht litnu
,thgil s’eldnac eht yB
,yltfos derepmihw anoiF
gnirettug eldnac eht
.gnihton ot denrub ylraen dna
eb ot thguo ti erehw saw sinep reh taht dnif ot desirprus ton saw ehS
taeh tlef ehs sa tfahs reh otno nwod daeh s’eireaf eht dellup dna tuo deirc anoiF
,sevooh emas eht no gnidnats
.esirnus gnidaerps eht sa roloc emas eht ,ruf der tnaillirb htiw
,ereht ni reh esahc mih tel ehS
.deen d’ehs sgniht eht lla htiw nwod dehgiew
.pot eht morf niaga nageb dna
,reh otni dnuorg eH
,teknalb reh dna seilppus reh fo redniamer eht pu dekcap ehs
.yawa dellup anoiF
,sgel reh neewteb delttes eireaf ehT
.tsehc sih ot reh gnildarc
.seert eht hguorht gnihsur ,gnitaralihxe saw tI
gnimocpu eht ni derutaef eb lliw krow esohw
.elbayojne eb ot trap siht detcepxe ehs ,sediseB
.pu deppihw dniw eht ,reh dnuorA
,aes tnatsid eht fo tnih tsetniaf eht llems
.erofeb seirutnec lliuq a htiw tfel dah rohtua eht noitnedni eht gnileef
.htab toh ,gnol a dna
elims a htiw reh decarg eH
.tnemssarrabme hcum oot pu krow mees t’ndluoc ehs tub skeehc s’anoiF ot hsulb tniaf a thguorb
.reh ni deddebme ylluf kcoc sih
”,yraropmet si tI“
.mih tsniaga mriuqs reh gnikam
,flesreh dlot ehs ,nooS
,psirc eht gnihtaerb
.reh gnicaf ,teknalb eht fo egde eht no tlenk dna
,nirg a htiw ,neht
.eugnot gnirolpxe reh ot htuom sih denepo neht
.reh fo edisni pu dliub tsul dna
,htgnel sih no reh gnivom ylidob
dloc osla saw anoiF
deddon ehs sa htaerb reh ni dekcus ehS
reh delcricne smra siH
,reh llif dees sih tlef ehS
,kcab ralucsum sih revo nar sdnah s’anoiF
.niatnuom eht fo edis eht gnola
.nemodba reh hguorht gniglub mih leef ot gnitcepxe-flah
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,sreh tsniaga dehsup erew spih sih litnu ytinrete na ekil tlef tI
”.lufituaeb ydaerla era uoY“
,lio elbategev fo tnip a
.erus eb t’ndluoc ehs tub
.thgis reh erujni dluow ehs taht deirrow
.ylikahs elttil a fi
niaga deppalf eH
.krab hcrib eht ni stner gniwalc slian ,deredduhs ehS
,pal sih otni nwod reh dediug eH
,reh ot nwod detaolf eciov s’eireaf eht ”?gnimoc uoy erA“
,htgnel sti htiw elbuort on evah ot demees eH
,tnuh rieht no gnipoows slwo fo eltsur tfos eht raeh
.tserof niam eht morf yawa tes
.naeco eht ni detcelfer ytic yawa-raf a eb thgim tahw
,htuom sih fo tuo pils reh gnittel
,emit driht a egassap eht detaeper ehS
,ecalp ni yldrawkwa derevoh ehS
.mih tsniaga dna pu reh gnillup
.mih ot esolc reh gnillup erofeb ezeeuqs a ttub reh evag
.ees ylerab tsuj dluoc ehs taht
,swalc rotpar erob regnol on tub
rehtruf dehsup regnif ehT
,lio htiw kcils ,sdnah sih fo enO
,reh ni deniamer eod eht fo trap emos ,llitS
pu smra sih dehcterts eH
.srehtaef yradnoces etihw dna strevoc nworb htiw
.sniol reh ni taeh gnidliub eht no gnisucof ,seye reh desolc dna
,tfahs reh fo edisrednu eht gnola gnilkcit ,regae dna
.sreh tsniaga delims eh dna
.reh pota debmilc eh sa nirg a sserppus ot elbanu
reh otni dellird seye neila siH
,reh edisni rehtruf dna
.deniater ehs htmraw elttil tahw tuo evird ot denetaerht dniw niatnuom gnilwoh eht dna
.reh otni repeed neve gnivird erofeb tuo os ro hcni na llup mih gnileef
.mottob reh no gnitser dnah s’eireaf eht tlef ehs litnu
.enam detsiwt sih ni delgnatne dna
,yksihw fo ssalg a
,tsim otni devlossid sehtolc rieht
snaej reh yb dewollof
.dees reh htiw htuom sih gnillif
.ssa kcils-lio reh revo gnidilg tfahs sih fo daeh tnulb eht tlef ehs litnu
,niar ekil gniraelc eht no llef thgilnoom yrevliS
”?rethguaD O ,niagrab eht tpecca uoy oD“
,gniraelc eht fo elddim eht ni tas anoiF
.reh fo tuo dna ni gnikcor flah
”acwP ehT“   :yojne esaelP
,reh ot railimafnu dna dlo saw egaugnal ehT
dehsinav nus eht nehW
.mih retfa drawpu tohs dna
stnemevom llams reh fo hcaE
.reh gnidoolf msagro sih fo taeh eht gnileef
.srehtaef dna sbmil fo elgnat a ni
demrofsnart eireaf eht sa pal sih morf dils anoiF
.drah gnitteg flesreh tlef ehs
gnihtyreve deniur wohemos dah ehs taht deirrow anoiF
ereht dennip reh tpek eireaf ehT
rehgih ylbaeciton saw nus eht
daeh reh detfil anoiF
.ria niatnuom looc
,staots fo riap a
.tsiaw reh dnuora reh gnitroppus rehto eht
.dehtaerb ehs ”,od I“
,ecanruf a saw eh ,mraw t’nsaw eH
.tserof eht hguorht ,did ehs sa ,gnidnuob
,reh revo flesmih depard neht
luflliks saw eugnot siH
elihw shgiht sih no gnizies swalc dekciw