.srehto fo draeh evah I tub ,em tsael ta si ereht
.sworht raeps rieht htiw gnorts dna swaptoof rieht htiw
”.uoy htiw ti erahs nac I dna ,taem deird emos dna retaw fo tib a em nevig evah slacol ehT
edahs lufituaeb sti ni tas yeht ,eert taht dnuof yeht nehw dna ,kniht ot ecalp
aicaca eht rednu
yeht esuaceb tub
,meht ot denetsil egalliv wen rieht fo snamuh dna sllong ehT
,lleW“ .tnemeticxe ni pu selkcah ,uneR deilper
secneserp gnileef detrats elpoeP .aicaca eht tuoba gniht suoiruc ylno eht t’nsaw taht dnA
erohsaes a ,sdaorssorc a ,xoniuqe na
nrob erew yeht woh ton srettam tI .neewteb ni tsuj
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,erew yeht ohw dnif ot delggurts syawla dah
.taht dnatsrednu ot deen dluow
.kniht dna tis ot eert eht ot emac srehto dna
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb ”neewteB nI sdoG ehT“ saw sihT
.rehtegot ,deid yeht ereh saw ti dna ,dlo werg anehS dna uneR ,egalliv siht ni ,ereH
,seye rieht htiw neek dna swap rieht htiw delliks
,dlrow eht otni gnimoc tsrif erew sdog wen eht nehw kcab ,oga sraey ynam ,ynaM
ytilanimiL  .moc.gnirpsyad-
”.nommoc oot ton er’eW
,egalliv rieht ni ereh thgir sdog wen owt nrob dah eert ehT
,syad ytrof retfA
,redle egalliv a fo ecivda eht nO
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,meht ot emac wen gnihton ,txen eht dna
:fo ecnivorp eht sa nees neeb netfo sah
.oot ti detpecca yeht dna ,taem emos meht dereffo drehpehs rehtona nehT
.edahs eht ni ereh
.sgniht was yeht gniyas detrats elpoep sthgin raelc no eert eht rednu dna ,dessap raey A
dna retaw meht dereffo dna ereht meht was
.deb erofeb rennid retfa
”neewteB nI sdoG ehT“
,flesmeht htiw noisufnoc eht elttes
?hcum taht rettam redle na fo lavorppa eht seoD“
.eerT s’revoL eht sa nwonk si ,srewop lacigam yb desufni si hcihw ,aicaca dercas sihT
.eert eht gnibrutsid ton
,segalliv ybraen eht fo elpoep eht ot anehS dna uneR fo yrots eht dlot yeht nehT
,ti ees uoy ,llitS“
emac uneR deman llong a yad eno nehT
.eert eht rednu tem elpuoc a ynaM
.pu gnitteg ,dednopser yeht ”,uneR“
.gnirpsyad-seyethgin ta dnuof eb nac
.ti fo enon evah dluow uneR
,setats delttes ro nwonk owt neewteb ni gnieb fo ytilauq eht—
”?neeb syawla evah I em eht ees yeht dluoc
.ma I ohw swonk esle eno on tub
.og dna emoc seripme nees sah ti dlo os si taht
eert eht rednu deyats anehS dna uneR
erew yeht tub ,neewteb ni tlef tsuj ro neewteb ni nrob erew yeht fi wonk ton od eW
.tseuq a sa siht was uneR tub
.deredisnoc anehS ”.eno ylno eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ligiv a no dnik emos fo nosrep yloh a erew yeht demussa slacol ehT
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,meht ot emac wen gnihton ,yad tsrif ehT .thguoht dna
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
em dlot sredle egalliv ym fo eno esuaceb tis I“
.aicaca eht rednu deyats yeht ,ecivda s’redle eht fo esoprup eht no desufnoc dna ,degnahc gnihtoN
taht dias srehto elihw
tas owt eht rehtegot dna
,klat tsuj s’teL“ .uneR dias ”,ton ylbaborp ,oN“
,syad ynam rof deyenruoj yeht ,suhT
erew yeht ohw tuoba
.noitcif ysatnaf fo evol a dna eeffoc rof tnahcnep a htiw flow a si seyEthgiN .kroW yraretiL lareneG tseB rof drawA rojaM asrU 3202 a now taht ,selaT llonG noitcelloc sih morf seirots eht fo eno
,sgniht owt tub ,gniht eno ton erew yehT
”.yllaer rehto eht ron eno rehtieN
gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN yb
oot yehT .uneR htiw tas dna
.yllufetarg ti detpecca uneR
”?eert siht rednu tis uoy od yhW“
,ma I ohw wonk I“ .llong rehto eht deksa
.dlrow eht ni aicaca rehto yna deviltuo gnol sah ti hguoht neve
.siht yned ot tpmetta on ekam lliw ew dna
.ereht rehtegot evil ot dediced dna
.rehtegot gniklat
,hsiruolf dna worg ot seunitnoc eert rieht dna
,llits stirips rieht dnif lliw uoy semitemos
”?em ekil srehto era erehT“
,detsixe sah drow nettirw eht naht regnol rof
eno si ereht tub
,htap a kcip tsuj ot
.rehto hcae ot noitcennoc dna evol fo esnes a dna
thgir eht gnikees ,eert
,sruoh wef a rof detatidem dna
edahs sti yojne ot
”,ma I ohw dnif ot
”?dnif ot drah taht uoy era dnA“ .uneR deilper
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.erew yeht tahw dna
,anehS dna uneR ot yarp
,yllaicepse ,redneg yranib-noN
.tuo ti erugif dna rednu tis ot eert a dnif og yeht detseggus saw ti
.tnereffid tuo emac I tub ,yob a detnaw stnerap yM .sey hO“
gnikniht tpek uneR tub
”,gnileef taht wonk I ,hA“ ”.rehtien dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
,yltneg syawla dna evol no ylno ecivda dereffo yehT
.ylenol tsuj erew emos tub ,erew yeht ohw no desufnoc erew lla toN
thgir eht gnikees
,ytilanimil tnerehni na ssessop ot tlef ylevitcnitsni neeb elpoep reeuq evah
.deksa yllanif llong dnoces eht litnu thgilp s’rehto eht fo erusnu
gniklat ,syad erom owt rof
.kniht ot emoc dah yeht dna ,edahs doog dereffo eert ehT .detser dna
.derewsna neeb sah ligiv yM“
gnol sa tsuj rof dna
.eert a tsuj saw ti dna ,enola doots ti
,erew syawla uoy uoy eht ees ton dluoc yeht fI
.skeew otni denrut syad dna
,sredneg eht neewteb thguac
,elam a ekil tfarc dluohs yeht llong eht dlot elpoep emoS
,sdog rehto eht htiw elur yeht ,rehtegoT .ecneitap dna
”neewteB nI sdoG ehT“
stirips eseht was yeht nehw rewop taerg fo
.t’nerew yeht gnihtemos eb ot meht detnaw enoyreve tub
,laiceps ylralucitrap erew yeht esuaceb ton ,llong suoiruc a erew yehT .detiaw dna
,eert eht dnuora demrof egalliv llams a dna ,emac srehto nooS
eert eht ot emac llong rehtona
ton ma I redle eht wohs dna egalliv ym ot uoy ekat nac I ,ekil dluow uoy fI
.noitatidem ni peed ,ligiv rieht tpek ohw uneR ot retaw dna doof thguorb yeht dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.gniggaw llat ,deddon dna daeh rieht debbob llong dnoces ehT
noigiler dna erolklof ni ytilauq yek a neeb sah—
.elamef dna elam neewteb ni syawla erew
llong dna ,namuh ,fle ,frawd ,seiceps lla fo srevol ,neht ecnis dna
.tneuqerfni si niar esuaceb ecracs era seert ,sdnalyrd eht nI
.llong dnoces eht dias
,eert eht rednu deyats uneR ,siht lla hguorhT
gnitirw sih dna mih tuoba noitamrofnI
.sevlesmeht ot gniklat ,sdnah gnidloh sllong owt eb dluow erehT
evol fo sdog eht
,sevil trohs evil sdnal eseht ni worg taht saicaca ytraeh ehT
tfiws ,elamef a ekil tnuh dluohs yeht
eert a rednu tis dluohs I
”.dnatsrednu uoy dna
evol dluow yeht revemohw dna
,sthgin raelc no dnA
elihw stoor sti neewteb meht eltsen ot luferac ,aicaca rieht rednu meht deirub elpoep ehT
.rekihhctih flowerew
eert eht rednu tas dna
,ti ot txen tuh a tliub dna aicaca eht fo edahs eht tfel yeht ,noisiced a ot gnimoc ,nehT .gnihgual dna
.saw dlrow eht tahw dna erew yeht ohw tuoba hcum denrael dna
.sbuc nrobwen rieht staert llong a ekil
,god.ecioveht ta
,namuh denniks-krad a ,drehpehs gnissap A
.esirprus ni pu srae ,uneR deilper ”?od uoY“
flesym hguorht kniht dna
tsuj dna eert yna gnidnif sa siht tnaem evah thgim redle ehT
.anehS dias ”,taht ekil d’I“
”.anehS si eman yM .seY“
,htob ma I tub ,rehto eht ro xes eno em gnilebal no tsisni yehT
tas uneR aicaca eht rednU .yawyna
uneR dlot sredle egalliv ehT
ruoh na rof eert eht rednu tis dluow anehS dna uneR ,thgin hcae dna