”retsaM gnilratS ehT“ saw sihT
,skaep eht gnoma sreets eh ,elbaremunni setik sih ,sdrib ehT
.daD regdaB yldduC
eert nmutua gnidaf a nopu dniw fo tsalb a seod sA
,sruoptuo riohc rieht snmyh ymrots ehT ,sraw elttil ,shpmuirt elttil ehT
.nik derehtaef sih fo ton eye yreve ot elbisivnI
,taefed nac tsepmet on rehtegot kcolf taht skcolf tahT
dnah sih morF .srednaw dniw dliw eht nopu yaw sih eh elihW
sdnats retsaM gnilratS eht gnihsur ria-dim eht dimA
,seog retsaM gnilratS eht sdrib fo edutitlum sih dimA
,ylf yeht erehw sdrehpehs dna llac yeht nehw meht sraeh eh hguoht tuB
.swonk gnilrats a ylnO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,peels ot uoy kcor seert taht ,reehsdniw tnorfmrots tsewhtron sA
,”retsaM gnilratS ehT“   yojne esaelP
seigolohtna noitcif lacirotsih eht ni krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.taebgniw dliw eht htaeneB
”nwaD eht fo thgiL eht nI“ ro
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,luos gnignis sti pils stel sevael nosmirc dedlig sti ni tahT
,llor ot ynomrah ni mih dnuor ,shguob nud erab eht morf pU
,sdnammoc tfiws sseldnuos sih ot mih dnuora leehw sgnilrats ehT
,yks eht hguorht sdrehpehs eh taht seciov dribkcalb eht sraeh eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
eerf dna tsaf gnisira ,hcaorppa sih ta kcolf eht stsrub oS
teews dna dloc si efil taht :wonk sgnilrats taht sgniht eht era esehT
.mih rof kool ot swonk nam on erehW
.htiw railimaf ylgnissap eb won yb yam uoy eciov esohw
floWcaM boR yb meop a
.dnammoc sih ot poows yehT
.skaeps reven dna ,selims eH .syenmihc dna sfoor eht gnomA
,daeh s'drib hcae ot ,traeh s'drib hcae oT daerht a seilf ereht elbignatnI
:yrotsih s'drib hcae swonk eH .noitingocer ni selims eH
.eid yeht yad eht litnu mih morf drow a raeh reven yehT
,sehtolc sih hguorht wollib taht ,no sklaw eh sdniw eht dimA
”,gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW“
,peek ot luos ruoy mih tsurt ,ekaw uoy erofeb eid uoy fi tahT
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf elbaliava
,teerts eht ni uoy evobA oot gnimoc neesnu sih ees yaM ,eulb tlaboc dna yerg duolc neewteB ,uoy dna ,ria ytpme eht nopU
.egap yrruFoS sih no ro
,ni hsur yeht dna tuo hsur yeht mih ediseb ,htaeneb ,evobA
.dnatsrednu dna raeh yehT daerd dna yoj fo hctiwt a ta oS
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
,nips xetrov gnirettulf rieht seod mih tuoba lla tibro nI
.daD regdaB yldduC
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.peed si yks eht erehw uoy dael ot mih tsurt ,eid uoy nehw dnA
,ees ot duola seirc dnA ,sraos dna ,sraef hcae thgieh yzzid ehT
.lortnoc ni ylerab nekow ,rebmuls fo shguob eht morf pU
.ylsseldne tsom tuo seirC
,floWcaM boR yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT
,skaerts ydniw eht tuc ot gnirts sih nopu etik sih si hcaE
teef drawyaw sih raeh ot yllufhctaw gnidoorb ,meht hctaw oG