.yad a ylraen ni netae t’ndah eh tub ,timov ot deirt eH .devaeh stug siH
…raeh uoy gnihtyreve eveileb t’nac uoy tuB
.rac sih ot tuo dereggats neht ,tnerehocni gnihtemos delbmum ,flow eht diap eH
.hcaZ ,reredrum a ton m’I“
.hgual ot detrats erugif ehT .kcilC
”?ew nac ,hguoht ,emas eht yas lla t’nac eW
.xobevolg eht gninepo dna rac eht otni kcab gnibmilc ,duola decnuonna eH ”.eniF“  .elbaxifnU
,nwod ti deton
.dias eciov ehT ”.oN ?uoy lliK“
.eno emas eht esu ew yltnerappA“
-  .yaweerf eht otno tuo
”!kcuf elttil yldrawoc uoy ,neht yawa nuR“
.ecnats gnithgif a gnitpoda ,detfihs lerriuqs ehT ”.yap
”.thgif a tuohtiw nwod og t’now I tuB“
,tihs fo eceip a saw hcaZ dna ,mih ot lufesu dna etilop htob m’I neviG
.yella na pU .rehtonA
.efas sih ni kcas eht dekcol dna teef sih ot tog hcaZ
.kcatta traeh a gnivah saw eh ekil tlef eH
.eb ot dedeen ti naht redrah ti gnidaer edam evird thgin-lla eht fo eugitaf ehT
.ni dnelb dluoc eh dedworc erehwemos rof gnimia
”.stnap ruoy ni ti tpek evah dluohs uoy sseug ,dab ooT“
.evird ot etats on ni saw eh
…nosniboR yrahcaZ ,llew ,lleW“
.ssenkcalb eht ni erugif eht tuo edam evah dluoc eh nrows evah dluoc eh evord eh sA
.peels emos teg ot deirt dna llam a edistuo tol gnikrap teiuq a dnuof eH
.deksa retnuoc eht dniheb flow ehT
.gab eht saw tahT .gab tahT
.ti eveirter ot tuo derepmacs dna tuo kcab debmilc eH .dnuora ecnedive eht evael tsuj t’ndluoc eh gnisilaer erofeb
.ygolohtna na ni raeppa ot tuoba eb yam eh taht era sruomur suoiciV
.rac sih ot dna rab eht fo tuo dluoc eh tseb sa deklaw eh tuB
.ti od ot derit oot raf saw tub ,nilanerda erif ot deirt ydob siH
.revoc enigne eht detfil dna tuo debmilc hcaZ .gnihtoN
.moc tod rettiwT morf
,moor eht fo renroc eht ni noisivelet eht no dehctiws flow eht sa zzub a neht ,kcilc a draeh eH .staes eht fo eno ot retnuoc eht morf dehcrul hcaZ
.renroc a dnuorA
.rac ybraen a dniheb dereep ylsuovren lerriuqs ehT .dias eciov ehT
,emit tsal eht rof rac sih fo tuo gnibmilc
.mood sih fo regnibrah tahT
”.hsac eht dah eh taht ffo em deppit eh
thgin tsal gnissim enog dah taht noitanod knaB caTaeS eht morf yenom nelots ehT
.wollof t’ndluow yeht tub ,nur d’eH
:esimorp a eb nac ti ,gninraw a ylno ton si yrots tsohg ehT .nethgirf ot tnaem ylno ton era seirots lufraeF
?snoitatnacni yeht ereW
.dehcrul stug s’hcaZ
.elttaeS sdrawot htron kcab ,ffo evord dna edisni debmilc eH
.mih gnihcaorppa saw erugif eht ro
.xob eht nettogrof niaga ecno d’eh taht flesmih gnisruc
.tey nossel ruoy tnrael t’nevah uoy wonk I tuB“
”.esac eht no dael eht laever ot elba si ohw ,senoJ syhR evitceteD htiw ereh ma I
tsaot no ysae revo sggE“
.mih fo tnorfni erots eht sdrawot drawrof derats eh ,niaga kcab denael eh sA
,erugif eht ot resolc gnivom saw eh fi llet t’ndluoc eH
,foor eht ta gnikooL
lufraF lacsaP yb ”ecnaegneV ezieS swodahS ehT“   yojne esaelP
.swodahs kcalb eht rof tpecxe
.ti raef ot esuac sah—
.roolf eht ot delbmut dna skcirb tew eht tsniaga demmals hcaZ .llaW .yellA
.efas sih ni dekcol saw yenom ehT
.nosniboR yrahcaZ OEC nwo s’knaB caTaeS yb dettimmoc saw tfeht eht taht eveileb ew ,seY“
,god.ecioveht ta
.gnimaercS .gnilwoH
,ytpme saw moor ehT
.sthgilteerts eht fo eno gnikcolb erugif eht ees dluoc lerriuqs ehT ”!seno devol yM
.txen eht ni dah eb tey yam
.krowtniap eht pu gnissem ,rac eht no gnidnal eert a morf kcits a neeb tsuj evah tsuM
gurhs a degnahcxe eW
.snoitpo rehto fo devirped ecitsuj ylno si egnever dnA
”?ti si em llik dna yrt ot gniog er’uoy os hO“
.egarag gnikrap eht fo tixe eht sdrawot ylwols rac eht
”.gninoitseuq rof mih etacol ot gnikool era ew dna egral ta yltnerruc si eH
”?naem uoy od tahw-
,ycavirp sih fo noisavni na hcus ta suoiruf eb ot detnaw eH
,tsom evol uoy elpoep eht tuoba gniracnu dna tpurroc eb ot sevlesmeht nevorp evah tnemecrofne wal eht nehw ,semitemoS“
,yella ybraen a otni delbmuts hcaZ
,dias syhR ”rotciV ,hctac tnellecxE“
.fo diarfa saw eh spoc eht t’nsaw tI
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.raef ni nruhc stug sih leef ylno dluoc eh tub
”.erofeb strap eseht dnuora uoy nees toN“
.ti tpecca ot demees flow ehT
.dednamed erugif ehT ”.em toohS“
,esuoh sih diar uoY
-  .ylpmis dias nam siocebeuQ eht
.tnemecrofne wal ot mih yfitnedi ot elba eb dluow retnuoc eht dniheb yug eht erofeb emit fo rettam a ylno saw tI
.thgin eht ni gniohce yrc sih ,demaercs lerriuqs ehT
”.won pots nac uoy …ynnuf yreV“ .thgis ni ydoboN
”.deipucco mih peek
,edis rehto eht no eno ehT .gnihton
ll’I tuB !era uoy tnur elttil eliv ,citehtap eht ekil nuR“
,teerts retfa teerts hguorhT
dna srenid ot mih gniklats
.flesmih ot dereens eH
.krap rac eht ot sriatsnwod gnidaeh dna rotavele eht ot gnidaeh
”.ecallaW kciR htiw sweN ylthgiN CBN ot emoclew ,gnineve dooG“
thginot yrots ruo ni nosniboR rM sa hcus—
.ti tsniaga dediced eh tub ,noitingi eht ni yek eht dnuora depparw wap siH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.em sdrawot gnileehw ,dedda enirevlow eht ”.gnitseretni
”.ti fo erus m’I“ .dias I
?woH .desu d’eh eno ehT
.nwod kcab tas I dna
.depsag lerriuqs ehT ”…ohW“
.sevil fo sdnasuoht evas dluow taht yenom elots uoY ?I dluohs yhW“
.rehtie rorrim eht ni gnihtyna tuo ekam t’ndluoc eH
.renwo s'eciov eht eb neve thgim eh ,lleH
…eb lliw erutpac sih tuoba truoc ni ynomitset siH“
”!oN“ .erugiF .renroC
.deraems dna derrulb noisiV
,llafthgin rof emit ni amocaT otni kcaB
.regna erup fo sthgiltops owT
.gnisol dna flesmih ydaets ot gniyrt ,taes sih ni demriuqs lerriuqs ehT
,evael ot tnew dna rac eht otni debmilc eH
.wap sih ni nugdnah a
.retnuh sih morf efas t’nsaw ti gniwonk ,tnemtrapa sih dediova eH
.ekawa detloj hcaZ .kconk ,kconK
.revo ti denrut eh
.unem eht ta pu derats hcaZ ”…hhU“
”?si ti yad tahw wonk uoy od ,yaS“
.part a eb dluoc gnihtyrevE
.niaga xof taht ees ot erab t’ndluoc lerriuqs ehT
.doog rof sruoy fo efil taht niur dluoc I
”?niaga gninnuR“
,depmuj ylraen lerriuqs ehT
,mih ta sdrow wen tips ot nageb neht eciov ehT
”.ecnaegneV .uoy dlot I“
.eciton s'tnemom a ta
.kcab nruT .erugiF
.deknilb flow ehT
.mih ot txen rallip eht tsap dekool hcaZ
retfa stsriht dna sregnuh eno rehtehw no sdneped lufraef si taht rehtehW
.ylmlac dias I ”.seY“
?ti teg ot talf sih otni nettog evah enoemos dluoc woH
.dias eH ”.ecnerefnoc a rof eludehcs dniheb gninnur …m’I haeY“
.tuc neeb dah tleb gnimit ehT
,ti htiw yawa tog eh fi tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.moc tod rettiwT morf ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer
,rac sih otni kcab camrat tew eht ssorca delbmarcs lerriuqs ehT  ?slleps cinataS
.thgin eht otni klaw ot gnitrats
.niaga mih dekcolb erugif eht erofeb
.xob eht denepo dna rehtegot draobdrac eht gnidloh epat eht ffo deleep eH
”.dnaltroP rof gnidaeh
.yenom eht fo kcas eht ta revo dekrims dna noisivelet eht ffo denrut lerriuqs ehT  ”…suriv SDIA/VIH
,ti nelots d’eh devorp dna ecalp sih otni tog I ecno
,lufraF lacsaP yb
.ti sdrawot dellorts yllausac dna irarreF sih ees dluoc lerriuqs eht tuB
?thgirla uoY“ .deliaf eH
”.htlaeH lauxeS rof tnemtrapeD latipsoH amocaT eht morf sdnuf gnissim eht yb yadot depmuts era sevitceteD“
.seye rebma thgirb esohT .dekaolc ,llaT
,tlah a ot diks d’eH
.telfael eht pu dekcip eH
,ydaets flesmih peek ot elbanu ,dnuora delbmuts hcaZ sA
”.secneuqesnoc on evah snoitca ruoy tahT
.nwod gnittis ,denialpxe I
.xob llams a tas irarreF eht fo dooh eht nO
.eciov eht ot decnuonna hcaZ
”?gniht ,SDIA siht rof eruc a dnif nac yeht kniht uoY“
.elbat eht otno pu ti gniworht dna repapswen sih pu gnidlof
.noitingi eht denrut eH
.swen CBN rof thgirW knarF si siht ,gninrom dooG“
.gniyrc ,seenk sih ot dils eH .ekorb hcaZ
.nekatsim neeb evah tsum yehT !elbissopmI ?woH
.retnuoc eht ot dereggats hcaZ sa dias retiaw ehT ”.gninroM“
.sehctulc s’ti ni mih gnivael
.ffo mih ees dluow reywal sih
.owt ylraen ni tpels t’ndaH
.kcab eht otni deraeppasid neht
.tnarraw hcraes eht teg dluoc uoy taht hguone gnol rof mih fo dir gnitteg fo esac a tsuj saw ti nehT“
.gnidliub eht fo sllaw eht gnissim ylworran ,devrews dna demaercs lerriuqs ehT
.sih otni thgir gnirats seye wolley ,dloB
.8 rehtruf a rof cisum dna
”.ecnaegneV“ ”?ereht s’ohW“
flow ehT .modnar ta ylraen gnikcip ,dias eH
W“ .ereht ydoboN
,gnikconk eht draeh d’eh erehw mih ot txen eno ehT
,htlaeH lauxeS rof tnemtrapeD amocaT eht ot denruter neeb sah yenom ehT“
.erehwemos morf gnimoc eb ot dah tI
.niaga leeh gninrut ,demaercs hcaZ
.renid eht edisni dereggats dna rac eht fo tuo debmilc eH
”.yad enO“ .deddon I
.ecnatsid eht ni deliaw sneriS
,niaga ssenkrad eht otni derats dna yek eht denrut eh
.emag a s’ti kniht tsuj uoY
,peels fo setunim no gnitarepo saw hcaZ ,won yB
.dnuora seert yna erew ereht fi ,taht deveileb evah dluoc eH
”.snworb hsah emos htiw
.emirc tcefrep eht
.niaga nur dna nrut neht
.kraprac eht ssorca xob eht gniworht ,ria niht no delbmuts eH
,dnah a dednetxe tI
,tsop eht tih eh fi rac eht latot ylekil d’eh tuB
,lleW“ .deddon syhR
.erugif eht tih ot kcab nrut dluoc eH
.ecno ta erehwon dna erehwyreve gnidnatS
,rood eht denepo dna rac eht ot kcab delbmarcs lerriuqs eht
.esac yenom knaB caTaeS eht no yadot etadpu na evah eW“
,dnaltroP edistuO
”.ot denetaerht ro
.regnol yna gnivird peek ot elbanu
”.ecaf evas ot meht rof eciohc tseb eht eb ot gniog saw pu dekcol mih gnitteg taht knab eht rof retsasid RP a hcus saw ti
.raef ni desluvnoc eH
.elbuod ees yletinifed won dluoc lerriuqs ehT
.reggirt eht dellup lerriuqs ehT
.tuc neeb dah seriw eht llA
ot gniog era uoy ,taht rof dnA
,deb ruoy edam uoY
?gniog saw eh erehw wonk yeht did woh dnA
.nees eb ot gnihton
”.relaed top yM“ .deksa syhR
.nwod ekorb eh fi ekirts ot ydaer yawhgih eht yb ssarg nO .deppots eh fi
.dedracsid dah enoemos pohs ybraen a morf xob a tsuj ylbaborP
.enif eb lla dluow ti
,neeb evah thgim tcudorp eht tahw gnirednoW
.detpurretninu elbat eht ot kcab repmacs ot gniyrt dna dereffo saw taht etalp eht gnikat ,dias eH ”.sknahT“
…I elihw hsac eht teg
,setats taht yenom eht htiw dedulcni saw eton a dna
.srotcennoc yrettab ,seriw gulp krapS
”?siocebeuQ ni mih ta gnilley
.peels dna letoh a dnif ot neht ,tsafkaerb emos saw dedeen eh llA
.flesmih eno ydaerla t'nsaw eh fI
.swodahs erom tsuJ
.dias noisivelet eht no retneserp swen ehT
.swodniw eht fo tuo deralg eH
.eromyna hsac eht evah t’ndid eh ,eruS
mih dniheb kool ot gninrut neht ,roolf eht neht
.eeffoc ym gnippis ,deilper I ”.uoy knahT“
,etteragic a til eH
.teef sih ot mih gnillup dna trihs eht yb hcaZ gnibbarg
.gninrom dloc a fo ezah eht ,nesir tsuj dah nus ehT
.gnivom saw erugif eht ekil demees ti
.erugif eht ta nug eht gnitniop ,niaga demaercs eh ”!oN“
”.erac uoy ekiL .eno rehtona rethgualS“
!ylimaf ym ot enod ev’uoy tahw roF
.wodahs ni degnulp saw dekool eh erehwyreve tuB
.segap yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF sih no
.dehca eH .derit saw hcaZ
”.ti tog uoY“ .deddon neht
.srallip eht fo eno fo tnorfni dootS
eno rehtehw ro ,ecitsuj
.kool ot dah eh tuB
goD fo tsohG eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
.renid lacol a ta tlah a ot rac eht dellup hcaZ
.”29‘ ,ht7 rebmetpeS“
,mih no regnif a dial reven I“
,lufraF lacsaP yb
,goD fo ecioV ehT no
.retnuoc eht ot delbmuts dna pu doots neht
”.detacol neeb sah
.pu ti dekcip dna rac eht fo tuo debmilc ylwols lerriuqs ehT
.ekawa gniyats ylerab saw eh dna gnideeps saw eH .taht fi
.deil hcaZ ”.enif m’I“
.nwod ti gniyrruh saw eh ekil gnikool tuohtiw tsafkaerb sih nwod yrruh ot deirt lerriuqs ehT  .dekcuf saw eH .ti saw sihT
.moor eht dnuora lla detrad seye siH
.daeh sih ni gnar sdrow s'retsnom ehT
”?uoy teg I nac tahw ,thgirlA“
mih llik ot gnitiaw sklawssorc eht tA
.gnideelb ,teef sih ot delbmuf eH
,noisivelet eht gnihctaw
,elbuort laer ni saw eh gnisilaeR  ”.ti ni eil won
,live eht dnatsrednu t’nod uoY
,2991 ,ht7 rebmetpeS“ etouq
.krad dna dloc saw krap ehT
.detnap dna dehgis hcaZ
,rac sih no seton citpyrc gnivael …yB“
.riahcleehw a ni enirevlow a ot enohporcim eht reffo xof eht ees ot pu dekool hcaZ
desae eH .enigne eht gnirif
.knird eht nwod gnicalp ,nageb I ”.,lleW“
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY ?uoy nac
,ciffart gnimocno otni gniwolp htiw sllac esolc wef a dah eH
.niaga nar dna dnuora nups lerriuqs ehT
.enod evah snoitca ruoy tahw wonk uoY
.dettimmoc ev’uoy tca suonieh eht
.pots-non thgin eht hguorht lla nevird d’eH
dettimmoc dah hcaZ
”.pu dessem lla kool uoY
.uoy dnif syawla
…seye wolley evah did eH
.niaga erugif eht rof yletarepsed ,dnuora gnikool ,sruof lla otno nwod llef hcaZ
,mih dnuora srac eht ni gnivirD
sraey 01 revo llew rof  seirots yrruf gnitirw neeb sah ohw
”ecnaegneV ezieS swodahS ehT“ saw sihT
”.hcaZ ,nur ot erehwoN“
.telfael llams a saw ti fo mottob eht tA
ehT"“ si yrots s’thginoT dna
,niaga revo dellup hcaZ
.yellA .renroC .yellA
.enif eb ot gniog saw tI
.rac eht ni kcab tas dna dnim sih morf meht dehsup eh tuB
”.hcaZ rof snworb hsah htiw tsaoT no ggE deirF“
.ni evac ot demees sllaw ehT
?efas sih ot noitanibmoc eht nwonK
,afos sih no kcab tas eH
.yrahcaZ ,em ot eil t’noD“
,niaga dellac eH
”?yenom eht delzzebme d’ohw eno eht saw eh taht ffo uoy deppit ohW“
.dnuora denrut dna ylprahs deppots lerriuqs ehT ”.tsal ta teem ew
.tlah a ot deredduhs hcaZ
.epacse dluoc eh tuB
.diov eht ot delworg lerriuqs ehT ”!reven I“
.neercs eht no hateehc eht ta pu kcab gnikool ,pu flesmih rehtag ot tseb sih deirt eH
.won thgir ni uoy nrut dluoc I
.eb t’ndluoc ti oN .oN
,peels ot dedeen hcaZ
.lerriuqs eht ta yltnelis derats tius epirtsnip eht ni rumel ehT ”?uoy era ohW“
nageb neercs eht no xof der ehT ”.sweN CBN rof ecallaW kciR si sihT“ .dnah ni knird
”"ecnaegneV ezieS swodahS
.htap sih gnikcolb doots erugif ehT
.ehtaerb ot deirt dna nwod tas eh ,edisnI
.dnatsrednu t’ndid hcaZ egaugnal a ni
.kcab kool t’ndid dna teerts eht otno tuo evord eH
,dlrow siht ni deined-gnol ecitsuj taht
.yltnalahcnon dias I
.niaga evaeh ot detrats stug s’hcaZ
,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daeR
roolf eht ot toof sih tpek eH
.resolc deppets erugif ehT
.erugif A .ylnedduS
,mih no dnah a dial gniht siht fI .now dah eH
,rab a edistuo rac eht dekrap hcaZ
.emoh ta efas yenom eht dah eH
”.sdohtem xodohtronu esu ot deen uoy
.ytpme eb ot demees xob ehT
daor eht ffo mih tnup ot deraperp
eht ot eruc a gnitaerc no gnikrow fo sepoh ni
,niaga yawa gnivird dna ti gnitrats
”.hcaZ did uoy tahw wonk I“
.thgif txen eht rof noitacol eht esoohc dluoc hcaZ ,mih wollof ot gniog saw retsnom eht fi ,oN
,CLL knaB caTaeS morf noitanod a erew noitseuq ni sdnuf ehT“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot