.wonk ot dedeen eH
.reh devol eh dna
.elbaresim saw ecnatsid taht lla ecap ot gnivaH
”yrarbiL ehT“   :yojne esaelP
.teprac nworb elbatrofmoc ni derehtoms
,wollof etiuq t'ndid eH
'.stludA' dekram ngis a rednu gnissap
sgnidliub dlo yb dessap tuobadnuor eht morf daor ehT
,yaw 'em gnissarrabme er'uoy ,pots'
;erehwyreve erew segnaro dna snworB
.tuoba wonk ot dedeen eh gnihton s'ti taht yas dna
rieht htiw ,etatse eht no sesuoh eht ekil ton
sdrawtuo rood eht dellup amaM
,dewaj kcals ,depag eh sa
!won emoh og attog eW !amaM ,nom'C"
!skoob ynam os dnA .skoob dna sruodo citsalp
.spu-nworg eht tuoba erac t'ndid eH
taht ni wap sih ezeeuqs dluow amaM hguoht neve ,duol tuo sdrow neddibrof eht gniyas ni thgiled ralucitrap koot eH
,wodniw eht ta rial rieht yb ssap ot spu-nworg yrawnu rof tiaw ni gniyal srotaderp ynit ees dluoc ydoboN
.gnivlehs eht ot selit teprac eht morf
,ereht ruoloc on saw erehT
,deksa eh "?amaM ,eew-eew ekil llems syawla retsillAcM .srM seod yhW"
si yrots s’yadot dna
.sevaw enis fo ecneuqes a gniyalpsid daeherof ypirts sih ,denworf eH
,koob-ypoc ecneics sih fo segap denrettap-erauqs no sgniward sih ekil tuo thgiarts gnippop sreksihw sih fo lla
.tnemeticxe desserppus ylerab fo naom a evag eh dna
,tsehc sih ot koob eht degguh
,oot deppots eh dna ,htaptoof eht no deppots ehS
revoc eht fo edisni eht no gat eht depmats ydal eht nehw dethgiled dna
revoc eht no tac derruf-gnol eht ,sraey ro
.hcaer fo tuo erew taht secalp esoht tuoba ssel dna
"!koob yrarbil ym daer attog I
egral a dah aera eht fo kcab ehT
-- drow a t'nsaw tI
,elims a htiw mih desiarp ehs
.ekatsim yb retnirp sih no yllanoisacco dna ,4 .loV gnaF ni
.steprac nolyn egnaro no deyalp yeht sa rehto hcae ta hgharg dna lwar dluoc yeht hcihw ni
saw sihT     .did eh ,os dnA
,koob eht fo enips eht dehcuot dna tuo dehcaer eH
,nepo rood renni eht gnihsup
,roolf eht otni tes llew dereit peed a neve saw erehT
.kcab dennirg eh dna
.amaM ta dekool dna leeh sih no nups eh dna
smoor gnivil delppad-thgil htiw sregit llams gnidivorp dna thgil ni gnittel
.ruf daeh sih gnilffur
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
flehs eht fo eerf ti dellup eh ,ylluferaC
.emit eht lla rehtom sih ot ylgniwonk gnicnalg
,deddon dna delims ohw ,nexiv eht ot dekool ehS
retsaf elttil a tsuj klaw dluow ehs dna
.etorw eh taen woh dias ydal eht nehw deppots ehs tub
... sredle sih rof noitaredisnoc evah dluohs eh dna
.thgir eht ot gnisopmi dna yerg dekool gnidliub enots eht dna
,ni nar dna wap reh morf flesmih desool eH
,thgirla saw eh fi mih deksa amaM
,nuf saw elcycib sih no ereh revo gnioG
.moc.sussatem no ro
!gnippohs gniog tsuj naht nosaer retteb a rof ti
;eulg-doow dna ssenwen fo llems suoiciled A
!stluda on erew yehT
,og dluoc eh erehw gnirolpxe tuoba erom saw dlo sraey neves gnieb ,won roF
.drow elgnis a saw revoc tnorf deruoloc-eulb eht nO
.nwal neerg llud tahwemos a otni dekool eh hcihw hguorht
llams a tsuj saw eh nehw
-- niaga ecar ot nageb traeh sih dna -- llitS
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
!rettam t'ndid ti tub
,pu-nworg saw eh nehW
... saw ti dna dlrow elohw eht ni gniht tseb eht saw sihT
.emoh morf klaw s'elim lluf a ebyam saw ti tub
sksid nedlog llams ot denediw seye ynwat siH
.enod htrae no krow sih redisnoc dna
taht ekil t'ndluow eH
,detarapes stluda eht retfA
. ylthgit ti dleh dna
.elpmis saw tI .reh yrram dluow eh
.licnep a dna drac fo eceip a tuo dleh dna
,mailliW teewS dna saep teews fo lluf
,rehcaet sih ekil elttil a dekool ehS
,enizagam nocorhtnA eht ni deraeppa sah krow siH
.tuobadnuor eht yb daor eht ssorc ot gnitpmetta saw ydal redlo eht erehw ot kcab gnikool
.ti no tac a fo erutcip a saw erehT   .daer ti ,"kissuoM"
.niaga wap sih deppirg amaM elihw
seirots erom roF
.noitnetta reh teg ot
"?esaelP ?amaM ,won kool og I naC"
.semit fo elpuoc a ekib sih no ti dnuora nups dah eH
;daer ot elbissopmi yllautriv erew yeht taht
retsillAcM .srM
."selaT droW 563" meht gnillac ,noitcif-orcim detimil-drow no neek ylralucitrap si eH
,ytfol dna dloc erew yehT
.devirra dah yeht taht ylsseldeen decnuonna dna
.esirprus reh ot ,delley eh "!eno tog I ,amaM ,eno tog I"
!yad eht saw yadoT
.sdnuorrus eht ta depsag neht
,ereht nwod erew ega nwo sih fo sbuc eerht ro owT
,desaelp dekool amaM taht yppah saw tub
,demaeb dna tnecs hsirepap eht deffins eH
.mih llet dluow ehs ,wenk eh
,daehrevo tfola yponac nedoow a dleh selop latem kcalB
.mih derongi nerdlihc ehT
"!ereht revo s'tI !kooL .amaM ,on ,naem I !ON"
.segap rieht no sgniward thgirb htiw skoob gnidloh dna gnihgual
,sussateM yb ”yrarbiL ehT“
.tuo taht esilanoitar ot elba eb dluow eh erofeb sraey ynam ,ynam eb dluow ti tub
.swodniw worran ,llat htiw
,elddim sih fo elddim eht ni sseniddig fo llab a saw tnemeticxe siH  sussateM yb
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy
.flesti yrarbil eht otni del taht rood elgnis a dna
.amaM ekil eb reve dluoc namow rehto oN
.dnuorg eht fo tuo gnimoc snoino fo sebut eht dna
.ecnartne eht ot yawklaw depols eht nwod ylnmelos deklaw dna enots eht yb dessap yehT
.noitcele na htiw od ot gnihtemos fo esuaceb nwot detisiv syawla eh dna ,'nwo ruo fo
.reh htiw klat dna pots ot dah ehs
,llaw noititrap eht fo edis rehto eht morf emac sdik reggiB  !woW  .wow tsuj
,gnihtemoS  .dekcol saw tI
.noitces 'snerdlihc eht ni yats ot mih gninraw
.duola sdrow eht daer eh dna gnidliub eht edistuo doots enots gib A .ylthgiT
pots t'ndid ehs dna
,yrots tnellecxe na nesohc dah eh taht amaM dlot dna
delims retnuoc eht ta ydal ehT
srettel ni dnuos A .dnuos a saw ti
.noitces 'snerdlihc eht ni yats ylniatrec tsom dluow eh dediced eh ,ylsuoethgir-fles elttil A
!tuoba lla s'ti tahw si siht oS
dehgis rehtom siH
,flehs dloc sti ot ti nruter ot mih ksa ton dluow ehs gnipoh
daeh sih fo pot eht no wap a decalp amaM
.elzzum sih ni edam srettel eht dnuos eht sa railucep sa dekool taht
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.eros erew teef sih ,won yB
.gnikrow saw nexiv ytterp a hcihw ta
.emoh kcab og ot detnaw eh rehtehw dna
"?naem ragoiT s'tahw ,amaM
,koob eht rof mih deksa nexiv ehT
.laiceps saw ehs dna ,s'esle eno-on
.erehwyreve erew srettel dna sruoloC
,wodniw ssalg-etalp
.gniwohs enips eht no drow elgnis eht ylno dna
.mih dlot ehs ,eman sih etirw ot dah eH
,nedrag neerg talf eht ot tuo ees ot elbanu neht
.sgat draobdrac fo swor elttil htiw gnihtemos gniod saw dna
.rood eht ot tnew eH
eno' ,dias ehs ,tnediserP eht retfa deman saw gnidliub ehT .mih dlot ehS
.selcric gninnips-reve ni zzihw ot demees syawla taht srac eerht ro owt eht htiw tuobadnuor eht tsap ,egdirb eht revo dna sllim eht tsap deklaw yeht sa
.sussateM yb ”yrarbiL ehT“
,tnatropmi yllaer saw ti fI
.skoob fo swor ynam ssorca ylluferac regnifwap sih gninnur
.ti otno mih gnikcol
,llud saw nedrag sihT
niaga eman sih ekops ksed eht ta ydal ehT .gnilims saw ehS
!gnirrrrroB   .sdnabsuh rieht ekil t'ndid ohw nemow dlo bmud tuoba ffuts diputs dna '...dias ehs neht dias eh dna dias ehs dias eh' llA
teg semitemos nemow woh tuoba mih dlot dna
taht teg dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,daeh sih deretne ,thguoht eugav a
... muesuM dna yrarbiL ragoiT"
.dnatsrednu ot mih tnaw t'ndid ehs taht sdrow delleps syawla
.puorg eht fo trap ton ,roolf eht no
sregit rehto fo shpylg delwarcs eht
,esruoc fo ,dna yb dessap sdneirf s'amaM fo enO
.daeherof sih dehsurb ylduorp dna
eman sih dellac enoemoS
,yob rehto on ekil mih devol ehS
,dloh ot nwo sih fo eno rof detsul eH
!yawyna hsibbur klat ylno yehT !riaf t'nsaw tI
.daeh sih revo og taht tel eH
ksed eht ot sertem ruof ro eerht eht deklaw yehT
wap sih dleh amaM
!ynam os erew erehT
.buc regit dlo raey-neves
:amam sih saw ehs—
.nexiv eht htiw tahc a gnivah saw amaM erehw ot ksed eht ot kcab nar neht
,skoob eht revo dekool ylwols dna
gniog fo maerd reven dluoc eh secalp otni mih yrrac yllautneve dluow taht gnidaer rof evol a mih ni trats dluow taht koob eht ,koob tsrif taht
,ti tuoba dessarrabme elttil a saw amaM esuaceb ,erongi ot evah dluow eh gnihtemos saw ti desilaer eh litnu
.daer ot snoitanalpxe dna segami ynam sa tsuj htiw
drow eht tuoba amaM gniksa no tsisni dluow eh
wodniw eht tseraen flehskoob eht ta kool ot denrut eH
shtnom rof ti ta kool dluow eno-on erehw
.ynam os gnoma morf koob eno nesohc evah dluoc eh woh derednow nexiv eht dna ehS ?noos oS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sedepicolev htiw demmarc saw dnats elcycib A
,taht od mih was amaM fI
,mih ot kcab ti dednah dna
,ekops yllausu ehs naht tfos erom saw taht eciov a nI
,smoor ssalg ediw ,gnol
,aera eht fo dne raf eht ot ffo dednuob eH
sreh gnippirg wap elttil sih
.seltit fo dairym eht dennacs eh sa lrihw a dnim sih
,ertnec eht ni hcneb der a htiw ,neerg mrofinu a
-- secaf lacirtemmys ylddo dna sdaeh erauqs htiw
.taen dna ecin srettel sih gnikam no detartnecnoc eh sa thgir eht ot dna tuo gnikcits eugnot sih ,deyebo eH
.yaw taht leef reh gnivah ni tniop on saw ereht dna
meht fo 563 evah ll'eh tniop emos tA
.thgirf ni pmuj spu-nworg eht ekam ot ssalg eht deremmah yeht nehw
,tnemom a rof deppots traeh siH
delbuoder ylleb sih ni selbbowylloc ehT
emac GNAB gniltrats eht erehw morf tuo derugif reve ydobon dna
,emoh ta nedrag-kcab sih ekil ton
.ega sih fo eno ot laeppa ylniatrec dluow taht eno dna
,ti edistuo saw eh dna ,llew eht denwo yehT
.mih ta nwod delwocs retsillAcM .srM nehw fracs reh rednu ecaf deppil-thgit
tluaf reh ton s'ti taht dna redlo worg yeht nehw 'kaew'
'meha' elttil a dehguoc amaM litnu amaM derongi ehs taht krow reh ni tsol os saw ehS
stnalp otatop no srewolf knip
.tuo eugnot sih kcuts dna pu dekool flow gnuoy A
,ezag sih thguac eno ,ylbakrameR
,stroffe sih tuoba gnihtemos dias ydal eht nehw derettit amaM
.ybab a t'nsaw eH .taht detah eH
ssenpmad yb deduolc os erew semarf ssalg edisni sretsop lareveS
.ytiniffA ruF no puorg "tpmorP yadsruhT" eht fo trap sa kcab emit emos gnitirw detrats sussateM ,dnalerI fo tsew dliw eht ni desaB
dedivorp sniatruc ecaL
,ten.ytiniffaruf no yhpargotohp sih weiv dna sgnitirw sih daer nac uoY
.srood demarf-der eht ot pu deklaw yeht os
.raef ni deirc evah dluow ehs
.enoyreve detrofmoc taht thgil esuffid a