.srobhgien ruoy htiw
.sepiw tew eht htiw denaelc d'ehs dalg reh gnikam
"?em naht reggib hcum os lla yeht erA"
,eson sih fo edis eht otno ssik a dekcep ehS
yawhgih niam eht ffo dellup ydloG
,dnim hcum meht yap t'ndid maS
saw serutcip ni nees syawla d'ehs sutcac lacipyt ehT
snrohgnoL fo shpargotohp demarF
,ruf deroloc nat emas
thgil a ta deppots d'yehT
.mih retfa delddaw maS ".oot ,egaggul ym s'tI .pleh emoc ll'I ,tiaW"
.teprac eht no liat reh deppals maS
?ecnelis ekil uoY"
daeh denroh sih koohs eh tub
"?dnuora pu werg I esoht tsuj rO
,lleW" "?em dna uoy tsuj saw ti thguoht I"
,mra reh detfil maS ".dreH
snroh sih fo eno debbarg dna
".eralg eht htiw pleh
.tsehc sih dnuora smra reh werht dna
.swonk tsewhtuoS ydobyreve taht gnihtemos ,naem I
,retsloH rehtorb redlo sih
.doots dna og tel yllanif ytteB
.reh ssik dna ni nael dluoc eh
.nwod teg ot gniog saw ehs woh
"?meht fo kniht uoy did tahw ,mu
"—yhw ,hu tub ,gniksa rof em evigrof ,mU“
"?seod tI" .deknilb maS
.sesutcac eht fo eno ta kool doog a tog ehs dna
gnorw og ot demees dah gnihtyreve erehw
d'yehT .tnemtrapa eht otni gnivom elihw snamreboD eht tem dah racsO .delims maS ".seY"
.skramdnal lacol tuo detniop racsO elihw
ediw tnew seye nworb ,tfos s'racsO
.tsud fo ffup a ni
rennid gnimoclew a detsoh
,emit emas eht ta
,esuoH yretsyM retsehcniW eht ni tsol niaga
,tcaf nI .reh htiw llits saw ytteB taht
”.emoclew uoy fo htob ekam ot tseb ruo od lla d’eW
,seye reh revoc ot nwod llef yltpmorp ti ,reh rof gib oot hcuM
.ydloG ta pu erats dluoc ehs os ,taes elddim eht ni gnittis
,oS" ".em nraw ot kniht t’ndid uoy yhw dnatsrednu nac I
,ylmirg dias racsO ",moM ,iH"
.ytinummoc a dna ylimaf a htob si dreh ehT"
.sreh fo ezis eht eciwt tsomla saw dnah s'ytteB
,daehrevo yks eulb raelc a morf nwod taeb nus ehT
"?mom ruoy teem ot teg I od nehw ,oS"
,daeherof sih debbur eH
,nwod saw ehs ecnO
.pu kcab doots dna gnidnatsrednu ni delims ydloG
,dreh eht gnivael ton m’I“
,mra s'racsO fo dloh debbarg dna
.ezeeuqs eltneg gnirussaer a reh evag dna
”.emit enola elttil a sdeen maS kniht I ,emitnaem eht nI
.sdnah sih otni swap debbew reh fo htob koot dna
tpecxe neht thgir deb eht no despalloc evah dluow maS ".ecnelis
.nees reve dah maS taht elbat nehctik tsegnol eht fo dne eno ta sdrac fo emag a gniyalp
reh nevig d'eh telecarb eht mih gniwohs
.moor ynit s’racsO fo tuo kcab yaw reh dekcud dna denrut ydloG ,taht htiW
".ti fo ekam uoy tahw si ytinummoc taht si gniyas m'I tahw ,yawynA"
.tsal eht naht elyts tnereffid ylthgils a ni tliub eno yreve
.detanicsaf saw maS
sehcuoc no dnuora gnignuol erew elttac fo puorg a ,edisni tsuJ
.reh wollof ot maS rof derutseg ytteB
,ylimaf si dreH“
.liops ot reh rof stik-dnarg tpoda ot dennalp yeht nehw neeb dah htuom reh fo tuo noitseuq tsrif eht hguohtla
lliw esehT" .sreh tsniaga deknilc telecarb revlis gnihctam siH
.ereht thgir rehtom sih htiw gnorw saw tahw mih ksa ot tnaw t'ndid tub ,denworf maS
.dnah-fooh a tuo dleh ytteB
.miws a saw moor ytpme na ni pan a naht erom detnaw ehs gniht ylno eht
.edis sih otni daeh reh gniyrub
.etam-dreh wen ym teem ot deticxe m'I ,sediseB
syawedis daeh reh gninrut ,dekcud ydloG
stneicnA eht fo lautiR si
.krow od t'nod stseuG .tseug a er'uoY"
.retne ot syawedis nrut ot dah ytteB taht rood dezis-lamron a dah eno siht tub
,taes s'kcurt eht no pU
,iH" ".ahtnamaS ,écnaif s'racsO si siht ,llA
.ytteB htiw ecarbme eht detpecca ylffits dna swap debbew reh fo seot eht no pu tog ylbatrofmocnu maS
"?sruo ot txen tnemtrapa eht ni elpuoc namreboD eht htiw sdneirf er'ew woh wonk uoy ,lleW"
htaerb peed a koot maS
,hguorht deklaw yeht sa puorg eht ot devaw ytteB
.rood eht hguorht tsrub ehs sa sedirts eguh
,ecnalab ot liat talf ,ediw reh gnisu ,seot-pit reh no pu tog maS ".tsewhtuoS
.redluohs s’maS no dnah egral a decalp dna
.flesym yb moor a ni eb ot lwarc ruf ym sekam syawla tI
,denruter eh hcihw ,guh a mih evig ot pu deklaw ehS
,osla tub ,meht dessim evah I"
,racsO gnitaerter eht dna reh neewteb deppets ytteB
epiw tsrif eht nepo deppans maS
.sessalgnus eht evoba srae reh neewteb daeh reh no ssik a tnalp ot revo denael dna dehgual racsO
dluoc ehs taht os reh sdrawot nwod gninael ,daeh sih denrut racsO
.meht dniheb kcurt eht fo deb eht otni sevlesmeht demmarc
.flesreh pots dluoc ehs erofeb srae reh revoc ot gnitfil swap reh ,kcab deppets maS
.nwo reh no ti deppolp dna
dekeirhs tsomla maS
.moor txen eht otni ytteB dewollof dna devaw maS
.won thgir tuoba kniht ot hcum oot saw sihT
”,maS ,uoy gniteem ecin
.telecarb tnemegagne esiouqrut-dna-revlis reh ta nwod decnalg ehs dna ediw werg seye s'maS ".ti
.mom s’racsO dezingocer ehs sa
.tsewhtuoS eht ekil ylimaf dreh eht fo yna evah t’nseod dnaltroP ecnis ,hguoht esirprus yb uoy thguac ti woh ees nac I
,daeh reh debbob maS
.pirt siht rof noitaraperp ni ylimaf sih tuoba tol a reh dlot dah racsO
.redluohs s'nos reh tap ot nwod denael ydloG dna
.flac a dna tik a htob tpoda ot yrt ot dennalp yeht taht noitnem ot deliaf tub
;taht ekil rehtegot meht gniees laerrus saw tI
?etam-dreH" .dekaeuqs maS ".etam-
,tsewhtroN cificaP eht ni pu gniworG
.esle enoyreve ekil tsuj mih taert ot deirt syawla ew hguohtlA
.reh ot kcab denrut dna deffins racsO ".sey
.reh ot nwod delims eh sa tnemesuma htiw decnad seye siH ".tsom dias I"
.deb eht fo egde eht no nwod tas dna
.gnikniht ro suovren saw eh nehw od racsO was netfo maS taht evom a
.drawrof reh gnillup dna
,tnatsid tnew seye sih dna ffo deliart eciov siH "...ekil s'tI"
”.demlehwrevo elttil a gnikool s’maS
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ytteB ta derats maS
,remmus tsal fo ecneirepxe citamuart reh gniviler
,retaw eht ni neeb d'ehs ecnis sruoh ruof-ytnewt revo neeb dah tI
.koohs dna tuo dehcaer maS ,ezad a nI
.gnirehtag eguh eht ni nees d'ehs nrohgnoL kcalb ylno eht
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.yrros m'I" .dehgis ytteB ".dnaltroP
seman fo lluf os ydaerla saw daeh s'maS tub ,snoitcudortni did ytteB ,niagA
.esnes erom ekam rehtom sih ot gniteerg citsaisuhtne naht ssel s'racsO edam noissefnoc s'ytteB
"?dnaltroP ot evom ot ti evael uoy d'yhw
.tnemom a rof derednop ehS ".hO"
,racsO otni denael maS "?srewolf
.ssarg ta gniwap saw eh ekil fooh kcab a dekcik eh dna denethgit wap s'maS no pirg siH ".eruS"
nepo dekaerc rood ehT "—s'ti ,oN"
.mih ekil ,erutainim ton saw ylimaf sih taht reh denraw dah racsO
”.gniddew eht retfa ni gnivom er’uoy snaem taht os ,sruoy rof dreh ruo gnivael saw eh su llet t’ndid racsO
esuoh eht ot kcab tog yeht litnu tiaw d'ehS
.egaggul reh rof dedaeh
,tuhs dehsoohw srood citamotua eht reh dniheB
".meht fo ynam os tsuj era ereht tub ,ecin si ylimaf ruoY"
.htaerb gib a koot ehS
,ecaf woc gnol emas
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,sdoohrobhgien namuh s'dnaltroP ni krow reh morf dezingocer ehs hcihw
,woc yraronoh na m'I fi ,oS"
sregnif ekil-fooh
,levan s'rehtom sih ot pu emac ylno daeh s'racsO fo pot eht
,ti wenk ehs erofeB
",’gnilbis‘ enifed uoy woh sdneped ti sseug I"
,relleK nosidaM yb
reh ta decnalg racsO ".era
ydloG deinapmocca dah taht snrohgnoL nezod-a-flah ehT
"?dreh eno naht erom fo trap eB" ".eM .sdneirf ruoY
.kcen reh fo ruf eht ta gnibburcs nageb dna
s'ytteB htiw pu peek ot delggurts maS
devomer neeb dah esuoh lanigiro
,eerht tas ylno kcurt s’ydloG taht lufetarg saw maS
,etad a morf kcab nettog dah racsO dna ehs sa gnineve enO
,noitaroloc yreve ni snrohgnoL fo enil gnol A
.emoh ta kcab erew ew nehw ylimaf sih tuoba em gnillet saw eh nehw yppah os demees syawla eh tuB"
.elttac delbmessa eht ta evaw dewap-elbuod a otni
.reh ot nwod daeh sih llup ot
.dnuorg eht ffo teef evif tuoba saw ehs
.trid eht no sevooh rieht fo sduht gnidnuop eht dewollof
.derehtoms tlef I
”.uoy sa stnerap lacigoloib emas eht evah ohw esoht naem I gnilbis yas I nehw sseug I“
.moor eht fo tuo ydloG tsap dehsup dna
.moor gninid a otni srood roiretni ediw-artxe eerht eht fo eno hguorht tnew yehT
,rood rieht fo edis rehto eht no tuo dellac ydloG
.racsO tuoba devol maS taht gnihtemos saw tahT
s'ytteB fo eno dnuora wap a gnipparw yllufetarg
fooh s'racsO ekilnU
.suovren llits saw maS
,ytteB ta erats ot denrut ehs sa telecarb tnemegagne reh gnihctulc
.kcurt s'ydloG fo taes tnorf eht otni sevlesmeht delkcub yeht sa racsO ot derepsihw maS
.racsO fo tnorf ni yltcerid deppots puorg eht fo woc dael ehT "!gnilrad ,racsO"
ediw tnew seye s'maS
,maerd a otni nellaf d'ehs ekil leef ot detrats maS
,kcurt eht fo deb eht morf yawa demaerts epahs dna ,ezis
"!hcnar eht ot teg ew nehw ruot a uoy evig ll'I"
.dreh eht fo tser eht htiw ni evom yeht gniddew eht retfa
,racsO ot ylthgit gnignilc ,maS ,ti wenk ehs erofeB ".ydloG
.uoy gnillet tuoba kniht neve t’ndid tsuj I ,yrroS"
,teprac eht otni fooh kcab daorb a deffucs ytteB ".ytinummoc
.wodniw kcurt eht fo tuo gnirats ,dias maS
.elgna emas eht ta pu devruc snroh rieht neve
.kcab evom ot tnaw t’nod I
.kool suoiruc a reh evag ytteB
”dreH nrohediW ehT“   :yojne esaelP
.oot ,taht htiw elggurts I tub ,poc a gnieb ekil I
,swap debbew nwo reh naht regral ylthgils ylno saw hcihw dnah-
”?thgiR“ .detatiseh ehS
.tops gnikrap eht fo tuo kcurt eht dellup ydloG sa snrohgnoL erom tey ta wodniw eht tuo gnivaw ,dias racsO
.potkcalb eht gnissorc sreets nrohgnol ezis-lluf fo dreh llams a laever ot yawa dellup VUS kcalb a dna
.kcurt eht morf nwod reh pleh ot woc eht gniwolla dna
.ahtnamaS ,dreH nrohediW eht ot uoy emoclew ot yppah lla er'ew ,lleW"
,eman ylimaf a fo daetsni eman-dreh a ekat yllausu eW"
".dreh eht dna su osla ,tuB
.meht ta kool ot denrut puorg eritne eht
.reh ta kcab dekniw dna dennirg racsO dna
,sdrawA yraretiL OEL owt dna ltoyoC a now sah ohw
ezis reehs eht tuoba
.epacsdnal talf eht revo derewot sniatnuom ecnatsid eht nI .hsurb egas dnA
,won rof tuB“ .maS ta decnalg racsO
,taes eht no doots dna tlebtaes reh delkcubnu ehs nehW
.seye reh teem ot gnisufer
.era uoy ezis eht er'uoy dalg m'I ,lleW"
.ylimaf citsaisuhtne s'racsO fo sserp eht epacse ot reh gniwolla
.seman fo yrrulf a ni yb welf tser ehT
,mih ta pu dennirg maS ".dnaltroP
.ssenisub ylimaf eht s'tI .sretneprac era ylimaf eritne yM
,esuoh lanigiro eht fo krowkcirb eht htiw gnihsalc noitcurtsnoc doow eht
snoitcerid htob ni deppots saw ciffarT
.deoom deb-kcurt eht ni elttac eht fo tser eht lla dna ydloG
.elttac eht fo lla morf emac sgniteerg dewolleb yppah ,erofeb ekiL
.egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna noitciF degnaF yb
.ecalp tsrif eht ni ti tuoba tuo dnuof d'ehs woh dna
.ydloG em llac uoy fi deronoh eb d'I .esruoc fo ,maS"
.racsO ,niaga uoy ees ot yppah os era eW"
.pets rehtona ekat ot flesreh decrof dna
.egakcap eht morf sepiw-tew wef a dellup dna ,ti deppiznu ,esactius reh ot revo delddaw ehS
.ffo gnippolc erofeb elims gniteelf rehtona ytteB dna reh htob gnivig
,hgual a tuo dekrab maS ".nwo
.ti naem t'ndid I fi desoporp evah t'ndluow I
.syad wef a ni gniddew eht rof ni gniylf saw ylimaf s’maS
.nwo ym no ti ekam ot koot ti tahw dah I flesym ot evorp ot detnaw I
.sraey eht revo otno dedda neeb dah tub
,esuoh hcnar namuh dlo na sa efil tuo detrats ylraelc dah tI
:ralimis os dekool yeht taht naht rehto tey
.dreh taht yb dednuorrus eb ot gniht tnereffid a etiuq saw ti tub
,seirots lanoitidda lareveS
.dnaltroP ot devom dna su tfel eh neht tub ,os thguoht I"
;reets nworb ytsud a
.ytpme yldesselb saw moor eht edisnI
.elttac htiw dekcap meht fo lla dna
epahs nroh nrohgnoL ni eb dluoc ereht noitairav hcum woh dezilaer t'ndah ehS
.spord niar fo tnerrot a ekil spil reh morf gnillips seman
.sraet dehsnu htiw dellif seye nworb ,gib reH
.sdrow s’racsO ta maS hguorht dehsaw feileR
",suomagonom t'nera elttac tsoM"
.reh ot sevlesmeht decudortni snrohgnoL fo dniwlrihw a kcurt dekrap eht ot yaw eht gnolA
.taeh eht ni gnilevirhs liat talf reh fo pot eht no niks eht leef dluoc ehs
.rentrap rieht htiw efil rof etam srevaeb wonk I"
.guh thgit a otni reh gnillup ,drawrof denael neht dna ffo deliart racsO "...taht
kcab deppets racsO
.elbaplap saw feiler reH ".racsO ,iH"
.ytinummoc a ekil si dreh a taht dias uoy ,tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.enog saw ehs
.delttar bonk eht dna
thgil a ta pots a ot emac yehT
.neht snalp gniddew eht fo tser eht ssucsid nac ew dna ,rennid rof nwod eb ll’eW“ .ediw seye reh
.yawa denrut eh dna sraet htiw dellif seye ediw s'racsO ,siht tA
,raey tsal mih htiw ni devom maS nehw
;etal oot saw ti tub ,nageb maS ”--ytteB“
.yllA dna ,nroT ,amrI ,evetS ,kciR ,boB si sihT"
.sdrow dnif ot delggurts eh sa htrof dna kcab gnikcilf
.rood eht hguorht tif ot ylthgils nwod gninael dna
.ekaw rieht ni deliart tsud fo semulP
”.ti tuoba klat ll’eW“
trihs s'racsO fo tuo tuons reh dellup maS
,moor eht otni rehtruf gnilddaw ,dias maS ",ti evol I" ".flesym
.tropria eht ta puorg eht ni swoc erutainim rehto yna nees t’ndah ehs tuB ?xiS ”?yllaeR“
,tsud eht tuoba reh denraw dah racsO
.sredluohs s'maS revo mra sih gnipard dna
.ereh ni tif I ekil leef t'ndid I
.tropria osaP lE eht ta ni thgir tif
,edis sti no tes etalp rennid a ekil dekool tI
,hsad eht ta derats dna detrons racsO
koob tsewen sih dna
”.gnivom dessucsid t’ndah I dna maS“
.emoh evom ot mih rof evol dluow dna mih ssim lla eW
".sdneirf tseb fo ytinummoc eritne na gnivah ekil si dreh a gnivah ,lleW"
.naorg a htiw reh otni pu dekcab racsO litnu tsael ta
.yawllah eht nwod detaerter ehs sa
.ria dloc fo wolf suoirolg eht ffo gnittuc
,yb dessap dah dreh eht fo tsom won yB
.meht fo riap eht revo demool yeht sa nus eht tuo kcolb ot demees sreets dna swoc evissam ehT
"?niaga evah uoy od sgnilbis ynam woH"
.ecaps roolf eht fo tsom pu koot deb gib A
.ezis s'racsO eciwt naht erom
.emag gniyalp-elor potelbat ylkeew rieht nioj ot god eht decnivnoc d'eh dna sdneirf tseb erew ognid eht dna eh
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”dreH nrohediW ehT“ saw sihT
.gnihtolc rieht fo tser eht yb deirub ylkciuq saw dna
erows ehs dna slirtson reh deraes ria yrd ehT
".dnuora écnaif ruoy swohs ytteB elihw egaggul yawa tup em pleh emoc ,racsO"
".nrohediW .srM ,maS em llaC"
.won thgir meht rof tnemtrapa eht gnittis esuoh erew dna
"!hcnaR nrohediW ot emocleW"
.eb dluow ti denigami d’ehs naht gnimlehwrevo erom tib a saw ytilaer eht tub ,elttac dezis lluf wef a dnuora gnieb eldnah dluoc ehs taht mih derussa dah maS
,trihs-t reh fo egde eht dnuora dellab sdnah tnorf reh dah ytteB
.lleh fo shtped eht otni dna tropria eht fo tuo delddaw maS  relleK nosidaM yb
,lufrednow os sti fI"
,I ma elttac fo dnik tahW
.hguorht deklaw racsO dna
neeb evah dluow dnomaid etihw s'racsO sa ecalp emas eht ni saw hctolps etihw s'ydloG nevE
.yltsenoh dias ehs ",duol er'yehT"
"!uoy teem ot eciN" "!ahtnamaS
.sekips elbisiv wef a ylno htiw
noitasrevnoc fo raor llud A
.ytteB ot kcab reh denrut dna daeh reh koohs maS
.sessalgnus eht no tup ot swap htob esu dluoc ehs os thgirpu esactius reh dellup maS ".sknahT"
.em ees ot deticxe os demees enoyreve tuB"
?su htiw evil ot gniddew eht retfa esuoh eht otni gnivom racsO dna uoy t’nerA"
”?gniddew eht retfa ylimaf ruoy htiw emoh kcab gnivom elbatrofmoc erom leef uoy
”?dnaltroP ot kcab gniylf erew ew demussa tsuj I sseuG …I“
;stops etihw fo gnirettams a htiw woc nat a ,ycuL retsis redlo sih ekil
".esuoh eht uoy wohs ot tiaw t'nac I ,no emoC"
.pu peek t'ndluoc ehs taht
.uoy evol I .enif s’tI"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
noitom eht denrut ehS
hguone drah neeb dah sgel trohs reh htiw ereh pu gnibmilC
".smelborp ym htiw uoy gnirehtob eb t'ndluohs I
.dreH nrohediW eht fo trap yllaiciffo won er’uoy taht snaem tI"
.elbaliava ecaps llaw fo kceps rehto yreve derevoc
.sdnapxe dreh eht nehw siht ekil syawla s'tI" ".driew saw tI
.kcab fooh sih ezeeuqs dluoc ehs os
t'noW .tniop a sah ytteB“ .dias ydloG ”,noS“
.eno gnihctam sih dehcuot neht dna
.sesutcac dnA .dnas hcum oS
.tcejbus eht egnahc ot deirt ehs ,daetsnI
.reilrae taht ekil gnihtemos dias uoY" .ediw seye reh
.efil reh ni stah yobwoc ynam os nees reven dah maS ,tcaf nI
.ytteB gniwollof yltnatculer ,dias maS ",thgirlA"
”.kcab evom ot reffo s'retsis dna mom ruoy tuoba deticxe yrev mees t’ndid uoy dnA“
,dias ytteB ”,racsO“
,sotohp s'racsO morf dezingocer ehs wef A
evah sesutcaC" ".srewolf tnaillirb tsom eht evah meht fo emoS
.teerts eht ssorca dednuop puorg eht sa
,roolf eht no saw tah eht
.nworf thgils a rehtom sih tohs racsO
,stops etihw htiw delkceps saw sreh hguohtla
.stelecarb gnihctam rieht ta nwod derats eh sa
,moor retfa moor ,sruoh
...taht ekil ti fo thguoht reven I"
”.ereh gnivil eb t’now ew tub
,dnaltroP ni kcab noitceffa retspih a sa ffo emac hcihw ,tah yobwoc ehT
,ereh ni tas elttac eroM
,revo wap reh denrut dna elims a mih evag maS ".em
.riah otni gninrut nageb tuons eht erehw thgir
.rewsna-non siht ta deknilb maS "?evah thgim I"
.egnahc reven lliw taht
.pu-ekam ruf htiw derevoc t'nsaw ti fi
.ruf nat sih sa roloc emas eht tsomla saw taht tah yobwoc nrow a htaenrednu morf tuo kcuts snroh ediw siH
,noos ot dennalp yeht taht reh derussa dah maS
ylimaf s’racsO fo erutan gnimlehwrevo dna
.daor devapnu na nwod depmub yeht dna
.roolf eht hcuot t’ndid sevooh sih woc ezis-lluf a rof dezis staes eseht no ,revewoH
.dreH nrohediW eht fo trap m'I ,tuB ?tahW"
.woc kcalb a ,ytteB retsis tsegnuoy sih dna
”.dreH nrohediW eht htiw llits era meht fo eerht ylno tub
,racsO sa ruf deroloc-nat emas eht dah woc ehT
,retal setunim lareves trapa ekorb yeht nehW
.ylippah deoom ydloG
”.oot reffo ym ssucsid od ,esaelp dnA .raed ,esruoc fO“
.boj reywal reh ta t’nsaw ehs nehw ybboh reh
.rof yrros eb ot gnihtyna evah t'nod uoY" ".yrros ,haeY"
"?rehtaf ruoy teem ot teg I od nehw ,racsO ,oS"
,tuB .ezis ym fo nuf edam reve eno oN"
,esion eht revo delley maS ",sknahT"
.evivrus ot revaeb a rof ereh yrd oot raf saw ti thguoht yletavirp tub ,deddon maS
elims gnigaruocne na reh evag racsO ,reh ot txeN
,dnuora denrut ehs nehW
?racsO dootsrednusim maS daH
.gurhs a htiw dias racsO
?reh ot desoporp eh nehw gnihtyna dias racsO t'ndah yhW
.ytteB htiw level eye ta reh tup tsomla taht
.ti dessik dna elzzum sih ot pu wap reh thguorb racsO "—tuB"
.dreh eht htiw gnola tpews saw
.steehs llaw-yrd tes yldab eht dniheb elbisiv erew smaeb eht fo emoS
,écnaif ym teem ot uoy ekil d'I"
.tpecca ot elpoep tsom rof hcterts a fo tib a llits saw revaeb a gniyrram reets a tub
,ruf kcalb evitcnitsid reh yb elbazingocer
”.dreh eht gnivael era uoy lla su nraw t’ndid uoy tub ,gniddew eht retfa dnaltroP ot kcab gniog eb ll’uoy syas maS“
eldnah esactius reh deppord maS
,meht revo demool taht woc nrohgnoL evissam eht ta ,pu dna
,ahtnamaS ,no emoC"
.rehtegot moor rieht ni enola erew dna
,pu dna ,pu derats dna
".dnaltroP ni rehtegot ,dreh nwo ruo ekam ll'eW"
.tesolc nepo eht edisni tas sgab s'racsO dna reH
,reh evol dluow yeht taht reh derussa eh hguohtlA
.em dna uoy eb ll'ti ,sey
.dnuora gnuws yeht sa snroh gib eht deye ylsuovren maS
.delims ytteB ",lleW"
.meht evoba sroolf wef a devil taht ognid eht htiw rotavele eht ni pu edor d'yeht
,snroh nworb ediw emas
.nirg a reh dehsalf dna
,sredluohs reh no mra s'racsO fo thgiew railimaf eht yb denedlobmE ".reggiD ahtnamaS
.eralg eht morf seye reh dleihs ot wap debbew a tfil ot maS gnicrof
.ezis llams sih fo esuaceb ,su fo tser eht sa emoclew sa t'nsaw eh thguoht racsO ekil tlef syawla I tey
.sregnessap pu kcip ot detiaw
"?naem uoy od tahW
,swonk enoyreve taht sgniht esoht fo eno s’tI
.seye reh neewteb elzzum reh no hctolb etihw evitcnitsid a htiw
.nrohgnoL a ekil leef t'nod I semitemos ,wonk t'nod I
.mra reh nwod dils dnab tnemegagne esiouqrut dna revlis ehT
,wodniw eht edistuo yb ylf yrenecs tresed eht gnihctaw edir eht fo tser eht tneps dna mih tsniaga dexaler maS ".ti
?dreh nwo ym morf yawa gnivil
.noitanicsaf ni gninetsil tas maS
,krow ot teg ot evah I“
,era uoy esruoc fO"
".ymmaS ,sepyt tnereffid fo sderdnuh era erehT"
,etad tsrif rieht derebmemer ehs sa delims maS
.llaw raf eht fo tsom pu koot taht
,selgna ddo ta esuoh eht fo tuo dettuj sgniw
evaw a ekil reh revo dehsaw taeh ehT
"!ruot eht uoy evig ot tnaw I
.eruS" .deggurhs racsO ".racsO
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
".uoy fo lla sevol eh llet nac I
".gnimlehwrevo elttil a s'ti ,uoy fo ynam os era ereht ,yltsenoH"
.dreh s'racsO fo emos tem ehs litnu
sepiw tew-ruf fo egakcap tseggib eht dekcap d'ehs dna
.sey ,ti tup ot yaw eno si derehtomS"
.gniddew siht fo esuaceb dreh eht fo trap deredisnoc eb d’I em gninraw ton rof yrros eb dluohs uoy ,sey ,ko ,lleW"
drawrof delddaw maS ".kcab
.suodnemert saw esion eht
.esuoh namuh a ekil ssel dekool esuoh eht esolc pU
,em sediseb sevlac rehto xis dah ydloG ,lleW“
.niaga kniht flesreh raeh yllanif dluoc maS dna
"?naem taht seod tahW
taht os rehtraf kcab tah eht dehsup dna dehgual eH
.dekil ehs yaw eht ni kcab reh nwod regnif devooh a nar dna dennirg racsO ".sdnapxe
.dednetxe moor eht dna
smra reh denesool maS ".rof
,aera moor gnivil a ekil dekool tahw ni
.pu-ekam ruf yb neddih saw ruf fo elgnairt etihw eht erehw
.snroh ediw s'elttac eht etadommocca ot ezis lanigiro sti eciwt tsomla ot dednapxe neeb dah yawrood ehT
daeh sih morf tah yobwoc eht debbarg
.ni tif uoy ekil gnileef ton dnatsrednu I ?ton yhW"
,fo draehnu ton erew selpuoc seicepsretnI
?dnaltroP naht rehtar ,ocixeM weN ni eb ot gniddew eht detnaw d’eh yhw taht sI
.kcab tuo nedrag sutcac a evah I"
.ylkciuq ti ot desu teg ll'uoy erus m'I"
.esactius reh otni erots eht ta dnif ot elba neeb d'ehs taht
.reh evoba pu esor
.hcaer ot maS rof hguone wol nwod dnah deppit-fooh reh teg ot revo dneb ot dah llits ehs tub
.ylsuovren gnitsiwt saw ehs hcihw
.reh ta delims racsO
.oot ,dreh ruoy eb syawla ll'yehT
srac fo enil a erehw bruc eht sdrawot
.ecaf gnol reh no kool deziladnacs a
.ti redisnoc esaelP“
,deppots maS "?tahW"
klawedis eht ssorca ffo gnittort nageb racsO sa eldnah esactius reh gnibbarg niaga ecno ,deksa maS
,seotpit reh no pu kcab tog mihw a no dna
",rellat erew sesutcac thguoht syawla I"
eht fo llaw a erehw delaever krow yrtneprac rooP
,yllufknaht ,letoh a ta gniyats erew yehT
.daeh reh koohs ytteB ".esle
,kcab dellac racsO "!moM ,gnimoC"
.maS guh ot revo denael dna dennirg ytteB ".dreH
gnirednow neeb yltsenoh dah maS taht
”.emas eht eb t’now tI“
.ydloG ,uoy knaht ,hU" ".moM rO"
redluohs reh revo kcab dellac ehs
,roolf rieht no ffo nettog dah racsO dna ehs emit eht yB
,sneppah ti semitemoS"
.esirprus yb thguac t’nerew yeht os
”dreH nrohediW ehT“
.ekahs eltneg a mra s'maS evag ydloG ".ydloG
wap reh revo dnah-devooh sih tup racsO
,dnaltroP ni ytinummoc nwo ruoy gnidliub neeb osla ev'uoY
"!yraed ,ydaerla evah thgim uoY"
.ti nihtiw laudividni cificeps yna htiw ton ,elohw a sa dreh eht htiw era spihsnoitaler dna
.gniklaw deppots ehs dna
,elzzum sih denepo eH
neercs a no emag reccos a gnihctaw
,kcen reh fo edis eht delzzun eh elihw talf dnats ot nwod kcab pord
.ydloG dniheb tuhs rood eht sa ezeeuqs lufetarg a mih evag maS
etomer a pu dekcip elttac gnignuol eht fo eno ,ni deklaw ytteB dna ehs sA
rof no og ot demees ruot ehT
.ecnelis desselb ,yllaniF"
.em tpecxe ,hguone dlo erew yeht nehw ssenisub ylimaf eht denioj sretsis dna srehtorb ym fo llA
dnuorg eht no sevooh kcab sih fo duht a htiw reh ot txen dednal eH .depmuj tsuj dna
.redluohs reh no dnah devooh a decalp dna
.tuo emoc ot sdrow teg dluoc ehs erofeb htuom reh gnisolc dna gninepo fo stnemom wef a reh koot tI
ytteB ecaf ot gninrut ,dias racsO
,ytteB yb denepo saw rood regnessap eht erofeb tuo teg ot deganam maS lla saw ",woW"
,edirts ni ti nekat dah rehtom nwo s'maS
sretsis s'racsO fo eno
.nees reve dah maS esuoh tseggib eht fo tnorf ni kcurt eht deppots ydloG
,kcurt eht fo edis rehto eht morf dellac eciov s'ydloG rehtom sih dnopser dluoc eh erofeb tub
"?ecrof eht no revaeb ylno eht m'I wonk uoy diD
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,ecno ta solleh rieht gniwolleb sreets dna swoc eht lla htiW
,mih ot derepsihw maS ",ffo wohS"
,moor rehtona tey deretne yehT
,edis rehtie oT
.elttac reggib eht yb dednuorrus eb ot tropria eht ta ekil tlef ti tahw gnirebmemer
.dnaltroP ni dreh nwo ym fo trap osla tub
.seod racsO ecnis uoy tpecca lliw dreh elohw eht
dna htiw evil ot sdreh rieht fo eno kcip moorg dna edirb ehT
.em ekil erutainim a sdeerb woc ezis-lluf a taht
,seiceps dreh a erew elttac taht ,yllautcelletni ,nwonk d'ehS .dreh ehT
.gnipag htuom dna ediw seye
.sneppah yllausu tahw s’tahT
,dreH nrohediW eht fo traP"
?retfa ro ega ym dnuora dreh eht otni nrob dlihc yreve gnitnuoc uoy erA .esruoc fO"
,daeh sih dekcud racsO ".gniddew
.serah fo daetsni elttac htiw emit siht ylno
".won dreh eht fo trap er’uoy ,lla retfA
.sreddu dna seenk woc ybbonk saw ees dluoc maS llA
.reh teem ot deticxe dekool meht fo llA
.wap desiar reh otni sessalgnus fo riap a gnippils
.meht fo owt eht dednuorrus dreh eht fo tser eht sa
"?yltcaxe ,naem dreh eht fo trap a gnieb seod tahw ,oS"
.edis eht fo tuo gnimoc smra tneb htiw llat
,nwod dettauqs mom s'racsO ".ahtnamaS
,relleK nosidaM yb
.mih drager ot kcab deppets dna
.yrd oot dna detaoc-tsud tlef ruf reh dna
,nedrag reh tuoba lla maS dlot mom sih elihw tnelis llef racsO
.racsO ta pu kool ot wap reh htiw pu mirb eht dloh ot dah ehs dna
srebmem ylimaf wef reh nraw dna llac retteb ehs dezilaer ehs tub
seye nworb ediw reh fo knilb delzzup a reh evag ytteB
,emit emas eht ta tuB
"?won eseht fo eno raew ot evah I naem taht seod
seye reh morf sraet dehsad ytteB
,pleh emos racsO reffo ot gnidnetni dnuora denrut maS
.tnew yeht sa tsud erom pu gnidnes
,revaeb er’uoy taht rettam t’nseod tI
.rethgual fo leep a tuo tel ydloG
seye eht ni maS kool ot tlenk ydloG
.enola tuoba mih htiw klat ot detnaw ehs gniht ynam os dah ehS
redluohs s'maS dnuora mra sih gnipparw
.stnalp tresed tuoba gnihton ot txen wenk maS
”,sdreh evah t’nod srevaeB“
bruc eht ta deppots yehT
neht dna ,VT eht detum dna
.detuohs htob yeht ”!on ,MOM“
.der gninrut srae ediw sih fo sedisni eht
.daeh reh fo edis eht nwod depoord srae s’ytteB ”…rednow I“
.tnecs gnitrofmoc dna railimaf sih ni reh gnipolevne
”!rennid rof emit ,maS ,racsO“
,dias ,dneirfyob reetS saxeT nrohgnoL erutainim reh ,racsO ",ereH"