,rehto ro tcilfnoc emos morf dnuow a
ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.tsrif ta sepor eht rof hcum derac I yas t’nac I
.gninruom ti fo syad suoicerp
.tog ev’I lla s’ti dna ,trid si eman yM
.thgin a rof ylno fi
tnecs tseilevol eht
,em tpurretni ot esaec ton lliw eh fi taht
,htob su ot dneirf a si ycreP
erofeb srehto eht desufer ev’I sa
.enim neeb ev’thgim eh
”.mih edam drol eht sa flesmih evol ylurt mih stel hcihw
.taht ta seye sih sllor noinapmoc yM
.tbuod on ,ekila erew eW
ereht dna neht secnavda ym detlah I
.em ot raed si eh sa rehto hcae ot raed sa
.dlrow eht morf snoitnetni sih edih t’nseoD
.ylgnidrocca seciv sih ot yalp dna
;wodniw sih fo tuo deppets dna
,pu kaeps nac eh erofeb xof eht ta daeh ym ekahs I
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
,dah ev’I seugnot ’sexof rehto ekilnu dna
,elat ym rof ecarb a tub si ruomuh ehT
.trap tluciffid eht ton saw
,ta detnih I sa derolpxe ton dah ycreP
,revewoh ,nworc sih erob ti sa llew sa yniturcs raeb dluoc kcen siH
.hcus ta kluab thgim nam ressel A
ynapmoc eht detseuqer dna ,letoh eht ta kcab devirra I nehw egreicnoc eht rof dellac I“
.gnivael ees ot sehsiler eno erugif fo tros eht sah eh ,yllanoitiddA
em smrofni srae sih morf kcilf elgnis A
noitpmeder ym stsurtsim xoF ehT
.dnatsrednu tonnac eh gniht rehtona teY .llet nac I
dluoW .traeh ym ni enevnoc lla sehca yM
.pup ylno na pu thguorb si eno nehw ruomuh fo esnes nwo s’eno spoleved enO
.moor gniward s’letoh eht ot elcnu sih denommus I
.evol ym dnuof I woh
stniop neetruof tnecifingam eht
.oot ,epoh mih stnarg etaruc I yromem eht fi sA
,niamer ot em rof saelp sih desufer I tub
.em erofeb dah I tahw
.nwo enim ot ssorca gnittimsnart ron ,ereht gniyats ytluciffid on dnuof elzzum sih dezarg hcihw elims eht
,eganortap ym esrubmier dluoc eh dohtem hcihw yb
.emit erom eno ecsinimer dna
eripme tsetaerg eht fo nworc eht rednu snorab fo enil duorp a fo nrob m’I tuB
,pu tnuom ot erised I dluohS
.deuqip saw tseretni ym
;sreltna nworc eht yrrac ot tnaem reven saw eh sa hcus eno taht mih dlot dah dna ,gnimoorg sih ro
.stseuqnoc ym gnoma ylgniraps noitceffa ym tuo denoititrap ev’I“
.sdrow dnoyeb das dnA .yldneirf dna
niaga thgin taht evil dluoc I taht
”.yaw elbaima dna tsenoh na ni flesym tneserp ot dluoc I gnihtyreve did I
.no nael ot enoyna dedeen reven
,tem tsrif I dna eh nehW
,niaga hturt eht mih dlot I os
.seirrap erom on dah eh hcihw rof ,tih tcerid A
.mar siht nihtiw denrub hcihw erif ecreif eht neve ton
,eno rof ylno saw noitativni eht taht dnatsrednu ot
.swap ym htaenrednu yaw gnisaelp tsom eht ni dedleiy ruf tfos sih dna
.nwoner emos fo tnemhsilbatse na
tuoba raeh ot ekil ton d’I fi sksa dna
.egnahc eht peek revres eht sgeb eh
,ecnedifnoc dnuofwen sih htiw
?I saw erehw ,syawynA“
.taht ta selkcuhc xof ehT
gnihtyna sa teews sa saw em evag eh kool erumed ehT
srednammoc dleif ecreif
.nommoc ni dah sknuks owt eht gniht ylno eht ton fi ,wef yrev eht fo eno saw doolb taht
redisnoc ot hguone denedlobme saw I
,yojne I hcihw aet fo tnairav detsaor eht dnats tonnac dneirf yM
daeh eldoop elbmuh ym no slruc esehT
.bulc s'nosillAcM driaL ot riap eht dewollof dna
.detaruc ecno I spihsdneirf eht sa wolloh sA ?spihS
.em htiw ereh thgir s’eh fi sa
,gnidnats laicos emas eht fo eb thgim I dna eH
,dlog ni ylno syap eH
.slarimda trawlats dna
,denruter I emit eht yb dna
.meht llac ot sreferp dneirf ym ,sruomaraP
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,ffutsyttopS yb
.stnegnat ym evigrof eh taht yldnik ksa I
?deb s’nameltneg rehtona otni snoisrucxe ynam ym fo eno rehtona ni ecnacifingis eht si ,sksa eh ,erehW
.efirts yna hguorht mrif dnats dluohs I
.dog morf tfig a saw eh
,mih dereuqnoc dah I sa em reuqnoc mih tel I
,daeh sih sekahs noinapmoc yM
.em htiw prahs gnieb mih revo ssentnulb sih ekat d’I tub ,eno siht ,tnulb s’eH
”.gninrom txen eht knim emas eht dnif t’ndluow I wenk I
.sevlesruo ot dah ew hcihw
,mih teem uoy fi ,siht wonK
;desluper neve ro ,yrgnA
.tuo deffuns tub lla saw deb sih otni em nevird dah hcihw erif ehT
”.dnoces on eb dluow erehT .tsrif ym saw eH
,gniriap doog a su deredisnoc yllaitini I
,ffutsyttopS yb ”roreuqnoC ehT“
,denimreted dna gnortsdaeH
xof eht mrofni I
.wonk seod xof ehT
,tfihs ot tibah tluciffid a ,yllanoitidda ,saw tI
,sah eh elims das tahT
.knuks eht ot noitativni eht dnetxe ot kcab tnew I nehw emac tahT
.devom ylpeed flesym dnuof I
.noitceffa sih llems dluoc I
smra s’esle enoemos ni ssenippah yraropmet dna ythgilf kees I dluoC
thgis thguac I sA
.ytinav ot laeppa siht rof llef eh ,esruoc fO
sgod dettops tuoba seirots erom roF
neht em now eH .eb dluow I
,xof eht llet I ,em eveileb tsum uoY
.dneffo ot hsiw t’ndid eh taht
em ot tnatropmi s’tI
.yrassecen snaem yna
.ecarg sih htiw pihsdneirf s’knuks eht etarbelec ot liatkcoc wen enif a deraperp dah I
.ecno saw I ekil ,dlob s’eH
.rehtaf sih tespu ot gnihtynA
.ytinav nwo sih ot ylisae os dneb dluow ohw enoemos evol t’ndluoc I
.em rof tsuj deilppa neeb dah erus saw I hcihw ,emufrep fo sreyal eht tsuj toN
.dellems tey ev’I
.eno tub seruliaf era sretnuocne ym lla ,seye sih nI
;elbayojne yrev ynapmoc ym dnuof salguoD“
,emac ssenkcis eht nehw tuB
,kcab elihw doog a ,yadnoM“
.emit erom eno mih htiw eb dna
”.efil ym ni tniop taht tsap ma I
.nees reve sah dlrow eht
.deneppah gniht tsegnarts eht tuB
,euh ro ruoloc yna
wehpen gnimrahc sih
,wap ym sekat eh ,daetsnI
.smra fo taoc s’rehtaf sih fo
.elihw a retfa daeh sih sekahs eH
?oot ydeerg eb eh dluoW
.smihw nwo ym gniniatretne dna ffo gnilooc
,sesiugsid fo derit s’eh em sllet eH
,esu ot elzzum sih tup I
.peek ot dewolla ma I sa hcus eno yteicos ylno eht morf
,detnemmoc driaL redlo eht
,tnemtrapa s’elcnu sih ni denevnoc eW
esolc tnecs sih leef tsuj
.cificeps eb ot mar A .yartsa peehs a del I ,yadirF nO“
.emas eht lla ereht mih tfel I
,nobruob dna yksihw fo noitcelloc s’elcnu sih fo dia eht htiW
.dniheb eulav fo thguan gnivael dna
.wap tfos sih fo hcuot rehtona tsuJ
,thgin taht etius sih ot kcab salguoD koot I
.oot dah elcnu sih
,edir a erised I dluohS
.raf yb gnidnats rewol a fo dna
,regnol tnemom a rof mih ta kool em tel tsuj d’eh fi
.yoj sih fo ecsinimer ot ffo kaerb tonnac dna ,yrots siht no sucof tsum I tuB
.si eh ,noitacifitarg etaidemmi fo xof A
.yteicos dna ssalc fo murdnunoc a htiw detneserp sexof no tnelaverp
.neddus eht fo lla ,rettib yllufthgirf s’tI
.erus m’I ,ot gnirrefer m’I eno eht wonk d’uoy
,evol tsrif sih yb emac eh woh
.egnarts era noitcartta fo seiroeht siH
.suomaf os reilitta’L sekam hcihw
tahw saw siht taht denialpxe I nehw detneler eh
.eno der a ,xof a fo epahs eht ni edam efil dna yoJ
”.tsael ta ,eno fo ecnalbmes A
.nees reve dah I eno tsenif eht saw elims tahT
.elat ym htiw no gniyrrac erofeb
.em dessarrabme dna sdneirf ym lla fo tnorf ni em enohstuo eh tsel
.sbreh htiw detarutaS .deneteewsnU
.mih nopu evol ym gnihsival tsiser t’ndluoc I
.semufrep fo noitacilppa lufretsam tsom eht rednu neddiH
.dednamed dog sih emahs eht yb dnuob saw ecneralC
.eh naht retfos dna reltneg rehtegotla si ruomarap siH
.emit ym erofeb em teem ot
,raeh ot liaf ton dluoc I taht hguone duol
.mih ot drow rehtona yas ton lliw I
.deneppah yeht sa meht yaler tub
.sih revo wap gnirussaer a tup I
,yrrac ecno dluow eh nworc eht fo thgiew eht raeb eh dluoC
.emas eht lla ,em htiw mih evah I tub ,mih ssim I
,taoc nworb dna der gnikirts sih htiw og ot eciov deniatniam yltcefrep A
.elbatnuomrus etiuq dna
.won su htiw ereh erew snoinapmoc ruo hsiw I woH
”.noitavresbo ym etaicerppa ton did eH
,gnigavar dna gnirednulp
.yrots denmad siht hsinif ot em ekil d’eh fi ksa I
.tbuod on ,scitilop fo dlrow eht otni rehtaf sih wollof ot seitlucaf eht sah eH
,rodatsiuqnoc sseltraeh ehT
,xof sih dna ,lesaew siH
,rentrap eno naht erom sreferp eh
.dneirf ym saw ereht
.ecreif dna etanoissap werg klat eht dna
em sksa xof eht
,reidlos a fo ria gninetaerht eht
,drawets s’drol a fo tnemiar eht htiw eriuqs A
.niaga mih ees reven dna
.mih sevres etalocohc toh fo puc a os
.aet fo puc looc ym ta pis I
.flesym desucxe dna
.mih tuoba gnihtemos saw ereht tuB .ydobon saw I
.elbakramer saw ralucitrap ni tnecs siH
.tneb lacigrutil eht fo kcub A
,erofeb eugnot prahs sih ot tcejbus neeb ev’I
.sehsidnevaC eladsnelG
etsaw dna efil ym rednauqs ot em tnaw ton dluow eH
.knuks dlo na saw eH“
”.bulc sih ta sdnim eht fo gniteem a rof htuos nwod
mih dnuora srae neek fo gnirettams A
.demmid osla era yeht
,trofmoc erised I dluohS
sdloh ohw loof dedaeh ria
.morf deliah eh htron raf woh rettam on
,nwad ot denrut thgin eht sa tuB
flesmih yb lla detseggus eH .ti detnaw ycreP
.tsenoh si nrael ot erised sih tuB
.hcum sa timda ot demahsa m’I
.enim naht euh fo rerup dna tnagele erom si sih hguoht
.flesmih sa hcus drial enif dna eurt a fo
.em htiw sterces sih derahs dah eh tuB
,kcab sih no revo dellor eh
,pohs aet a ni xof A
.neddortnwod derdnik eht fo doohrehtorb a sevlesmeht dnif tonnac snoraB
.yteicos hgih fo syaw eht nrael ot htuos emoc ,roinuj ym owt ro raey a
.stseuqnoc ym lla fo tsegnuoy eht saw leinaD ,ytnewt tA“
.no yrrac I taht ytluciffid htiw si tI
;lleh fo semalf eht saw tI
- mih nopu tsurht dah yteicos elor eht emussa hsidnevaC ekam dluoc I
.rehtaf sih fo tcejbus eht morf eugnot sih tcartsid dluoc I ecno
,eugnot ym tew ot
.erew ereht ynam dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
dedulcxe eb ot snaem ti tahw wonk tonnac eH
,mih tuoba lla saw rof ksam on dah eh hcihw tnecs tahT
.hguoht ysae os ton s’taht syad emoS
.desseug evah llits d’I
.ssel gnihton dna ,trapmi ll’I tahw si hturt eht ,dog yb dna
,derdnuh a ni enin-ytenin htiw etaicossa ot em swollasid knar yM
.edam reve I tseuqnoc tsuj ylno ehT
,pis rehtona ekat
.kaeps ot os ,esrup nioc ym denethgil
.elzzum s’xof eht no tuo skaerb elims A
.elat ym morf efil eht lla gnivomer snaem ti fi neve ,kluab reven dna
eht morf ,hsidnevaC drakciR htiw gnineve ym tneps I
.tsacdop siht no seirots rehto sih tuo kcehc ot erus eb
.mih llet I ,ecnetsisni s’dnabsuH ym nO
?esirpretnE ?sdnaL
.tuohguorht edis ym yb neeb s’eh
,htaerb rehtona ward ot ecaeP
?thguoht ev’dluow ohw
.mih tem ev’uoy esoppus t’nod I“
em llet thgim eh fi ksa I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tfos dna dnuor si ssentnulb eht dna ,dnik si eh tuB
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,won evael tsuj dluoc I
.ecidujerp dellac eb ylerab nac dereffus evah I tahw taht
.evarg eht ot yawflah m’I hguoht sa leef em sekam ruogiv sih
,tnemailrap fo rebmem rehtona fo dlohesuoh eht ni kcul ym thguos I ,yadsruhT“
.rewsna ot woh wonk t’ndid I hcihw sdroW
,speek eh ynapmoc eht etadommocca ot ytud s’nameltneg a si tI
swonk eh eldoop ehT
ynapmoc eht ni dekcab thgiarts dna llat dnats ot elba eb ton dluow
.taebtraeh rehtona rof
.laitnetop htiw gnitsrub
.edam dah I ssem tahw was I .detaefed
.sraey eht revo em ni swalc sti knus dah breh eht sa
.taoc enimre suoegrog taht htiw eno ehT
,M elbarenev eht hcaorppa ot erad yllausu t’ndluow I tuB
.evah llahs eh tahw si taht dna
.taht retfa em htiw salguoD koot I
.elddas ym saw ereht
.thgin eht rof deb sih erahs ot detnaw I fi deksa ylkeem eH
.eman nwo ym wenk I sa erus sa
.erus m’I ,tcepxe ot emoc ev’uoy sa
.eno was I reve fi ,tsilaud A
mih mrofni I nehw tuB
,tpels eh litnu detiaw I
;meht dniheb noissap eht enigami ylno dluoc I
.fo esu edam srotisiv sih fo tsom tixe na
.esolc mih dleh I nehw ylballortnocnu kcilf dna hsal dluow liat sih dna
.won redaorb selims xof ehT
,renommoc a fo elims ysae eht
.knard ytic eht ni seidal dna sdrol hgih eht lla
.yrrow t’ndluohs uoY
,egrahc ni eb ot ekil saw ti tahw tlef eh fI
.deets ym saw ereht
,rof hsiw reve dluoc I sa dneirf a eurt sA
.lettahc sa dlos llits era
os saw ti yhw gnirednow sruoh dneps ot desu I
.nettogrof t’nsah eH
.ylsuoiruc stlit daeh s’xof ehT
.emit siht flesmih ot snoitseuq sih peek nac eH .aet ym ta pis dna
.seigolana noitarolpxe eht morf niarfer ot
.won ,gnorw taht lla saw eh erus os ton m’I
.kcab emac eh fi dlohserht eht ta mih pots ot telav ym dlot I
.llew wonk I mohw ,der taht ,traehteews a fo gnihtemoS .nis sa kcalb
.nruter seiromem eht sa elzzum ym no tuo skaerb hcihw elims neddibnu eht morf smets ti spahrep rO
demia neeb gnol dah sthgis sih hguoht
.ssel gnihton ,erom gnihton ,wenk I ,evol saw tI
.tfos ton s’eh ,dog yb dnA
.wenk I thguoht dah I tahw dnoyeb dlrow a em dewohs eh dna
.mih fo hturt eht dah I ,noos dna
,eman eht ezingocer ot liaf t’ndid eH
.wollof sexat ym tuoba noitseuq ylekil A
.doog yna od ylerar sdrowS
-- sdrow nwo ym ni -- mih deksa I os ,gnitarg tahwemos werg tI
.elbatrofmocnu yldediced saw sih
.wonk t’nod I ,wohemos timsnart nis ym tseL
,stpmetta sih citsaisuhtne woh rettam on ,noinu ruo morf gnirpsffo on eb dluoc ereht ecniS
,seye sih ni flesym tsol tub ,deugirtni saw I
”.noisausrep knim eht fo
.gnineve taht flesmih ot esuoh eht dah ohw ,nos sih
,sdnekeew ym dneps yllausu I erehw
,sdneirf erew eh dna xof ehT
dewotseb I erehw
.sgod rof evol on dah eH
.nopu nael I hcihw hcturc a
.tsrif ym saw eh fi em deksa eH
.sdrow s’elcnu sih tbuod knuks gnuoy eht ees dluoc I erows I tub ,deriapsed I
,erahs ot dehtaol esiwrehto saw knuks dlo elbaresim eht hcihw
,hturt eht detnaw eH
.elat eht morf em tcartsid ti tel tonnac I
,srieht fo noitasrevnoc emos draehrevo gnivah ,desilaer I
.saw eh erusaert a fo hcum woh tsuj em no denwad ylkciuq tI
.eldoop ed emèrc rof etiteppa suoicarov a htiw ,dnuoh a tub
.war taorht ym edam sah klat siht llA
mih dlot I emit s’tI
.ti gnitnuocer m’I sa ti fo thgil ekam ot flesym gnirb tonnac I dna
,revewoh elzzum ym nepo sa hcum os dluoc I erofeB
.seilfrettub nellaf rof yarp ot desu eh
,ytixelpmoc dniheb selat gnirucsbo rof rail a deman eb ot htaol d’I
.elat dlabir ym rof nosaer emos htiw mih hsinruf t’nod I fi evael ot snetaerht dneirf yM
.strosnoc lauqe erew yeht fi sa meht sevol eH
.smret relpmis neve ni
.rehtaf sih dnuora yltsom devlover klat sih ,yad taht ynapmoc sih nI .sey hO
.ecnarongi sih ta ylthgil ffocs tub pleh tonnac I
.gnidaeh saw I htap eht nwod eunitnoc t’ndluoc I
,efil ym fo sraey enin roF
;erusaert a t’nsaw eH
.doolb gniliob sih delooc dna eugnot prahs sih detnulb dah I
,htderdnuh ym saw eh fi tub
”.tcepsorp eht ta detavilas
stnemmoc xof ehT
.em morf elbat eht ssorca dneirf eht seod sA
.terces tsepeed sih
.dlofnu yrots eht tel dna ,kcab elims ot yrt I
,dedulcnoc dah gnikamevol ruo nehW
hcihw sdeed dna sdrow wenk eH
.mih ot kool detseretni na htiw drawrof snael xof ehT
.htaerb txen ym detnaw I naht erom mih detnaw I
.taht erofeb ecalp sekat yrots siht ,ton srettam tI
.noitseuq on saw erehT
,yb tfird ot neppah hcihw slamina fo sdnik rehto yna ro
?ytsanyd s’rehtaf sih rednu tlef ylerar os dah eh sa
.mih esufer ot edur eb d’ti ,yldab os ti detnaw raed roop ehT“
.tif ees I yaw yna ni demrofsnart eb ot ydaer
,yngivA’d noraB rueisnom gnuoy eht fo ynapmoc eht deyojne I ,yadseuT nO“
,eno thgir sih no eussit racs eht hctarcs ot stnaw eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ekat thgim ti gnol woh rettam on
;mih evah ot dah I
.wehpen lagidorp eb ot noos eht fo
,yrotciv teews fo detsat eH
.egnarts os ruoivaheb ym sdnif eh yhw si hcihW
?rethgiarts klaw dna
,ylraelc os ti ees nac I
,rettiwt no mih dnif ro ,egap yrrufos sih no eye na peek ,ylevitanretlA
.lla dna stluaf ,saw I ohw rof em tpecca d’eH ?tcefrep os enoN
.yngivA’d M ekil enihs tonnac ylpmis
.od ot em dlot traeh ym tahw tsniaga dekcub I ,yllautcnitsnI
noihsaf tcerroc eht ni nrow slruc taen ym htiw ,syawla sa erugif gnihsad emas eht tuc I ,yldrawtuO
tnaw ton dluow eH
.yrots elohw eht llet I taht
,sedapacse nwo ym fo mih dlot I .nrut ym saw tI
ssenkcis eht yats t’ndluoc edalb sih htiw sseworp s’xof eht tuB
,seitrap nwo ym fo eno ta neve
.elat ym eunitnoc I
.htiw nees eb thgim drol yna naht
thgil derutcarf ehT
,dnabsuh ym htiw setutitsorp erahs ot desu I esuaceb
d’eh retfa ,did I
.lanif ylrettu os erew sdrow siH
,elcnu sih ot ylniatrec dna ,mih oT
,ereht dna neht em fo tseuqnoc a edam ev’dluoc dna
.teews dna erup os gnihtyna rof deyarp reve elagnithgiN rehtaF tbuod I
,secnalg yhs sih rof neeb ton ti dah nevE
.wonk ot thguo dog fo nam on
,reilitta’L suomaf eht ot nar I“
elbat a gniruceS
.eod yna sa lufituaeb sa skool daeh dereltna-nu ,htooms sih mih dlot I
yllacificeps erom ro ,smra-ta-tnaejres eht
,niav a si hsidnevaC .mih
.erew reve yeht sa raelC
,oga sraey tnuoc tsol dah I
.hgual ot em rof tluciffid si ti ,yadoT
.peels sih htiw elbuort evah ton dluow knuks dlo eht
gnuoy era seye siH
.dnal ngierof a ni rellevart railimafnu
.noitcellocer ym fo liated eht ni thgiled I
.tnemtrapa sih ni dniheb wehpen sih evael tsum sdeen eh taht dna
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
.sesicrexe lacov sih nopu detnemmoc I nehw em ta tuo dehsal kcub ehT“
.em ni erised a tliub dah klat ruO
fo evitpecer yllauqE
.stsoc lla ta dediova no ereht morf dna ,dereuqnoc neht
,mih ot noitativni na dereffo I
.dleifthgiN rehtaF ot drow a tsuj saw ycabileC“
retcarahc nwo ym ni stluaf dniheb meht erucsbo ot ton em dnuob ruonoh yM
,staoc etihw gnihctam ruo rof ylno fi
.ytic siht ni dneps dluoc eh emit tsenif eht eb dluohs gnitruoc siH
.yllarutan rewot a morf gnillaf engapmahc fo elttob a sa deppots sa niamer ll’tI
;euqinu saw em sdrawot ecnailpmoc sih ,eninac wollef A
yojne esaelP ffutsyttopS fo
.secnereferp ym wonk yeht dna ,enim fo tnuah a si pohs aet sihT
.snomres detaeh sih rof nwonk si dleifthgiN ecneralC rehtaF
.sdrow emos dias eh nehT
.mih ot flesym decudortni I
,ma I taht nortap dnik eht gnieB
edisni yaw ym klat ot deganam I
,gniddehs tsetal sih retfA
.ylesolc oot meht etarobale t’nod I os
,thgil detcelfer htiw rettilg yeht hguohT
,derolpxe ecno ,nees evah ecno thgim rehtaf sih segnar niatnuom dna stresed tnatsid
,sevom elzzum siH
em sdrawot puc srae kcalb gnimrahc s’noinapmoc yM
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.sexof eseht ,tcnitsni kcap oN
,edis sih ot esolc ,mih htiw tpek eh ,revewoH
,wonk llew uoy sa ,setutitsorp htiw railimafnu ton ma I“
,enola erised yb dnuob eb reven nac I
”.kaeps ot os ,gnidaeh s’pihs eht morf weksa
;em ediseb knird citamora eht morf pis peed a ekat I
,mih yfsitas dluoc evol fI .erised ylnO
.llew mih swonk xof eht dna
,meht rof detiaw ,tuo kcuns I
.hsidnevaC ekilnu ,elbmuh saw eH
.noitasrevnoc sih dna
reilednahc eht fo thgil eht ni enivid dewolg eH
;neht thgil wen a ni dehtab saw eH
,taoc deniatniam yllufituaeb sih fo
wap eltneg a htiw mih ecnelis I
”?wonk uoy ,seye esoht erew ereht nehT
,noisserpxe detartnecnoc
,taerg eht ekiL .gnitniap a ton
.rehto eht ro eno esoohc ot thguo d’I taht
,elytsefil sih yb deugirtni ma I hguohT
smialcorp dneirf yM
.gats nworc eurt a emoceb s’eh kniht lliw sdneirf sih
.denmad eb noihsaf dna ,sekil eh tahw sraew eh os
.moor gnikoms eht ni knuks dlo eht dnuof dna
?siht lla gnillet m’I yhw srednow xof ehT
.emas eht ton erew ew tub
elzzum sih ni neve dna ,esrup sih ,swap sih tuoba dlog erom dna
,yob a sA .leinaD ekilnu
.ti revocsid dna rof hcraes ot em gnitivnI .hsitteuqoC
.doog fo ecivres ni erew seil eseht
.yratidereh saw ”gnirolpxe“ rehtehw
,dneirf lautum ruo dedausrep I yadsendeW nO“
.tcejbus eht hcaorb dluoc I erofeb
,ytic eht ni letoh demotsucca ym ot detaerter I ,yadrutaS nO“
.mih nopu ynapmoc suomaf ym fo erom
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.I sa emas ,seye esoht erimda ot desu eH
.ylsuoipoc os ffuts luof siht knird I yhw
.latnemitnes mih derugif I
.noisseccus kciuq ni eciwt mih dereuqnoc I
,aet fo puc driht ym rof tiaw ot kaerb a ekat I sA
.nwo sih otni sknis eh repeed eht
.yppahnu em ees ot dnats reven dluoc eH
,yenom dedeen eh tuB
.elzzum sih spots tahT
.nem gnuoy elbatcart rof yrtneg eht gniruocs ,dnuoh gnuoy sselmia nA
,htuocnu na saw I ,traeh ym edisni tuB
.siort à eganém lausac a htiw
.yniturcs morf efas eb dluow eh
.”eb thgim“ toN .em dlot eh
,mih hcaer ot kootrednu I yenruoj eht dnatsrednu tsum eno
.rehto hcae tisiv ot detnaw yehT
,denrael dah I tahw mih dewohs I
,god a tsuj ton s’eH
.tibah eht fo mih nekorb sah ruomarap tsrif sih tub
.yadot mih htiw saw eno taht hsiw I woH
.ecaep evah I ,elihw a rof tuB
.rehto ro tcilfnoc emos ni rehtegot devres yeht eveileb I
ffutsyttopS yb ”roreuqnoC ehT“
htiw detaicossa ecno saw eman tneicna ym tuB
.flesym ot peek I yrots eht fo tser ehT
”.eganortap ym htiw mih ecarg dluoc I ylno fI
.seitud yldnabsuh ym mrofrep ot elbanu saw I taht
.nwo ym morf tsurht latrom a htiw eugnot prahs sih pots yllanif dluoc I ,der fo elttob driht eht retfA
,tsrif sih eb dluow I
.em esipsed tnecrep eno tsal eht dna
.seye sih sehcaer ylerab hcihw
.nameltneg emas eht fo gnikniht er’ew fi sksa eH
.yadot yllaicepsE
,eciv dna nis rieht rof kcolf sih snmednoc eh erom ehT
.rennam detavargga na hcus etiuq ni enoyna htiw sdrow degnahcxe modles evah I
yllacitcarp eh ,nettogrof tub lla naidraug a sa seitud siH
.mih ot tsaob ot naht retteb wonk dluohs I dna
.ta kool ot levram a saw eH
.lleps eht kaerb ot tnaw t’ndid I
”.wohs drawtuo na tub si ti taht
;elpoep lamron sa ton tub
seye sih yaw eht
,tsrif ta suoibud hguohT
.nwod sih yal dna tuo siht krow ot gnol os xof eht koot ti dezama m’I
,savnac knalb a fo em dednimer eH
,nosillAcM driaL yb
,tros elbatcepser ,deniartser a saw eH
.niaga elims em edam won sah
,nameltneg gniripsa nA .salguoD
.xof eht htiw og ot em detnaw ev’dluow salguoD
hguohT .tpmorp tuohtiw detnaw ew tahw wenk eW
,nioc emas eht ni troter dluoc I hsiw I
puc aet ym fo pis rehtona ekat I
ereh moor yreve ni rehtona ro nameltneg eno fo tseuqnoc a edam dah I
.deedni ylteews yrev dna ,riohc a ni sgniS
.efirts morf nweh toN
.evael ym ekat dluoc I dna derruls werg hceeps sih litnu detiaw I
.resim a saw rehtaf siH .raed roop eht
.suoiruc dna ,gniugirtnI
.noitanalpxe ym ni raelcnu neeb evah thgim I gnikniht ,dnatsrednu t’ndid I
,mih naht htrib rewol a fo saw I
.yldnik meht taert dna llew meht yap syawla I tub
.em ni detnioppasid eb dluow eh thguoht I
.sediseb gnisimorp dna
.selbram sa htooms tuc
,elzzum sih ot ekar tnagele dna eltneg a dna srae dnuor tfoS“
.hguone etiuq si keew a ni yad enO
.esiop ym niatniam nac I gnol woh rof wonk t’nod I
yldniknu ton em sksa noinapmoc ym tniop siht tA
.ni nioj tonnac I
.seirots esoht fo hguone draeh s’eH
.nees d’eh tahw wenk I erofeb syad eht ni kcab ,mid
,yldniknu ton ,skramer xof ehT
gnilraD leinaD deman retniop A
.pihsnoinapmoc dna evol fo smret ni sretnuocne ym dnatsrednu ylno nac eH
.noitcefrep ot dehsurb
.yrtnuoc tnatsid a ni yawa seugael fo sdnasuoht
elpoep erehw dnal a morf semoc eh taht tegrof semitemos I
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
”.keehc dna elzzum sih no ,seititnauq taerg nI
.morf si xof eht erehw aet rieht neteews yehT
ereht saw ti wenk I
.dluow I eveileb I .driht eht
,sreep ym sa emas ,dog fo ecarg eht yb detnarg si eltit ym tuB
?niaga dnuora emoc reve dluow
.seye gniremmihs nwo sih ot dedda
.timda ot erac I naht erom em ot mih sraedne hcihw ,smrahc ynam sih fo eno s’tI
.seye s’xof eht ni thgil a s’erehT
.stsoc lla ta dediova eb dluohs saw I sa elbbar hcus taht
,mih sevres xof a revenehw dna
.seod eh sa nwod gnikcilf srae sih
.enod dna dias si lla nehw ,thgir si hcihw taht rof evirts I
”roreuqnoC ehT“ saw sihT
.desirprus eb ton d’I
.hgis a tub tuo semoc gnihton tub
.tnavres a tub ma I dna
.flesmih fo noinipo na hgih oot
detibahni yltnerruc saw tnemtrapa tsompot ehT .eno tub
.dehcatta worg mih tel ton dluoc I
”.em sdrawot secidujerp sih ksam ot stpmetta on edam eh dna
ffo meht swohs eh dna ,remmus txen ni emoc od yllanif sreltna sih nehW
,ytlarimda eht fo drol dna rerolpxe taerg eht fo nos ,ycreP rebmemer uoY
,seye sih ni tnilg eht yb gnigduJ
,em ot raed os reve si eh hguohT
.enim mih deredner ylurt dah tseuqnoC
,nees reve d’I yna ekilnu ,serihppas gniremmihs owT“
,elihw a rof dewaj eW“ .eunitnoc tsum I
.snoinipo suoitnetnoc
.noisseforp dlo eht sekilsid eH
.edih ylurt nac emufrep on tnecs taht dekrul meht htaenrednU
,riohc sih fo evorppa t’ndid rehtaf siH
.yngivA’d M a tem sah eh taht
,siht no sgnileef ym dnatsrednu tonnac xof ehT
,das dna lufyoj si ti tuB .oot ,ot thguo I
.hctam tcefrep a ylerus
.ot neddibrof saw eh sa neve ,driaL nrehtron eht tsiser ot erised A
.eno egnarts eht si ohw eh si ti taht wov I
.tnaem dah eh tahw ton saw tuB
,yromem ym ni hserf stseuqnoc tsap ym htiW
.emoh ym ot emoc ot ,rraC lavicreP
,su etarapes sraey evif ylno
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.emit
.taht ta delims ev’dluow ohw ,oga gnol ,enoemos ecno saw erehT ”.regnuoy eht ...yaM-
.tey tsud ot enog ton evah yeht drol eht knaht I
.niaga pu sthgil eh ,elat eht fo taem teews eht dehcaer ev’I taht
.tcejbus taht revoc ot dnuora gnitteg m’I taht mih dnimer dna
sih yb derednihnu
”.srotcelloc xat dna sffirehs denroh gnorp fo enil gnoL
,saw eh tahw rof knuks eht ees dluoc I
mih devieced I .etatse
.won htap nwo sih no si eH
em ot dessefnoc eh
,sevirra aet ym nehW
,hcaorppa ym wolla ot mih decrof
.gnissap sih tneverp ro
”.flesmih sa nis ni dehcnerd sa enoemos evol reven dluoc eH
taoc sih htiw ,ereh dneirf ym ekil toN
.rennam ylmeesnu dna tcerid tsom eht ni
.htrae eht otni enog si salguoD ym dnA
,tnemecitne elttil a htiW“
.yoj htiw dellif seye sih dna ,dleh elims siH
.snomres sih ot denekil eb dluoc hcruhc eht ni sgniteem ruO
,ruf etihw dna kcalb sih htiw llew tnew taoctsiaw dna trihs enif siH
.mees dluow ti ,deb ym otni hsidnevaC gnuoy raed evord emahS
,ycreP ekilnU .yngivA’D ekilnu
”.mih evah ot dah I
.seramthgin ym rof erutxim labreh a em evag naicisyhp ym kcab elihw A
traeh s’nam a fo trap taht kcolnu ot ksat nevig dog ym si tI
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.selims dna sdon dneirf yM ”?rraC reiniaR riS
.gninrom eht ni tfel dna degavar ,dereuqnoc eb ton dluoc eH
.revo yek eht dnah ot mih rof ysae ton s’ti wonk I
?dniheb seye esoht evael I dluoc tuB
,enim tsniaga hcuot yltneg dluow liat sih yaw eht ro ,gnikool t’nsaw I thguoht eh nehw derednaw
,revewoh desserpmi ton si xof ehT
”.neht gnis eh did ,yoB
.tnemtrapa nwo sih derised ycreP“
.retaw hgih ro lleh emoc ,mih htiw thgin rehtona ssim ot ton erows I
eman eht rednu lla
.ot desu nworg d’I noitcaer a
.llew seirots esoht wonk I nehw neve ,dnoces sih dna
,elims em ekam dluow hcihw sgniht elttil eht llA
.stseuqnoc ym fo yna htiw nees eb ot ton em llet netfo uoy wonk I
.xof a erew I taht dluoW
;evol ym dnuof I woh dnatsrednu ylurt oT .dethgis trohS
s’hguorobsniaG ekuD ta ytrap a ot deviecer flesym dah I hcihw eno
,yas ot efaS .mih loof eroM
,sksa xof eht ,yngivA’d M rof elttes ton I dluoc yhW
?rof deksa eh yrots eht htiw od ot lla siht sah tahW
.rehtegot dnoces sih dna mih thguorb ohw I saw tI
.tiw ym demialc sah traeh ym ni ehca eht tub
.mih ni flesym ni detah I tahw was I .ekila ooT
,daeh sih dehsurb I nehw reviuq dluow srae elttil sih yaw eht rebmemer I esuaceB
.ylsuoires erom siht ekat ot thguo eH
.siht xof eht llet t’nod I
tsom sih em sreffo xof ehT
--eno gnidnammoc eht-
.enola mih yfsitas ot hguone neeb evah thgim ’tnemyap‘ ym
.tsae eht morf aet detsaor enif a
.nori kcalb morf nweh egac a ni dekcol si traeh siH
peels peed a hcus desuac erutxim ehT
.revewoh ,seye s’leinaD ni evol yna t’nsaw erehT“
.salguoD teews ym htiw thgin eht eruces ot emehcs a dehctah I“
.flesym deruonohsid dah I
.gnimoorg ni sthgiled eh hcihw
,elat lufhturt a xof eht desimorp I ,sala tuB
.tnereffid saw leinaD tuB
sruomur esoht fo tcejbus eht sa devarped sa enoemos taht ,thguoht I yltneuqole ,denosaer I“
,emoh sih ta htob era
,noitasrevnoc ruo ni flesym tsol dah I ,revewoH
eh sa hcus enon taht llew lluf gniwonk ,yad txen eht
,seinoloc eht fo nameltneg A
.oot erusaert a si eno rehto ehT
,dnim ym gniduolc noissap htiW
,enod dna dias si lla nehw ,erutcip a si eH
.erahs ew yrotsih eht yb deduolc si noisiv s’dneirf ym tuB
,driaL erem a yb dewoc eb ton dluow I
.sutats ro htlaew ym ni tseretni on dah eh