.reerac sye rof doog eb ll’siht tbuod t’nod eW
.tsael ta
ecnahc ffo eht no tsuJ
s’taht… .em ot gniklat neeb t’nsah taht eno eht er’uoy
!erutcip a teg dluoc I erofeb ffo deppiz tI
jbo.elpoeP_ehT_fO_tsaL
.ylraelc ,gnimoclewnu dna gniddibrof kool ot dengised s’tI
.uoy htiw tesrats eht hctaw ot detnaw I
.riaf s’taht dna
.saw nosrep siht ohw llet dna rehpiced nac
.hgU .enoemos rO
*** druM— ?siht ot ereht si esoprup tahW
deirt I tub
!krow ruoy fo evol eht
,emit tsaL  .nogard delcatcepseb eht
,erehwemos krap troser ecin a dnif
,lleW ?klat ew naC
eerhT oreZ seR telaD
,rotacirbaf eht hguorht nacs eht nur ll’I spahreP
,me evresed t’nod I yas d’I
!hguoht dloc yreV
.did yllaer I
?sgol ruoy gnidaer saw I thguoht uoY
.yrtiucricorcim dah yehT
…naem I !sruoy gnidaer neeb ev’I
,od ot evitcudorp gnihtyna fo ecnesba eht nI
seirots rieht fo erom dna esoht dnif nac uoy dna
,srotsecnA
:TNEMHCATTA ELIF
.dnuobmrots llits er’eW
.gnizilibats/gnitartenep/elam a ni taht etaicerppa I
,elihw a rof taht morf tser ot desoppus erew uoY
.gnisaerced s’ti kniht I
?neeb t'nevah uoY
,rorriM eht gnitagitsevni neeb ev’I
,erew yeht reveohW
.gnorw leef serutciP
,efas era eW
.ytiroines muesum eht rof troper a
serutcip gnikat deredisnoc eW
.noomyenoh reporp a evah
nijaZ pelA eH yrtnE *** nlaF dna druM—
.taht ekil t’ndluow ye tub
.nwo ruoy er’yeht elihw evol fo syad ruoy evol tuB
,lateM .eutats a sa debircsed eb ylno nac tI
eniN owT lmiG teH yrtnE *** nlaF dna druM—
.noitasilivic ruo ot tenalp siht morf egassem lanif eno
,luos eht tuB
,detapicitna I sA
.eramthgin s’esle enoyreve saw noomyenoh ruo saw thguoht d’I tahW
strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,haeY !erew eW .evol roF
srotceted noitaidar tuo tes ev’I
,dniheb gnilgnad sliat gnol dna sllehs tub gnihton ekil kool yehT
rehtie nlaF dna ,cilohocla yltnetop yrev eb ot devorp derevocsid ew stiurf eht fo enO
,sfeirb miws ni gnizama kool ot seunitnoc druM
.dirg erauqs a ni degnarra
,gninraw fo ytnelp evah
,riapsed t’noD
?espalloc lacigoloce adnik emos ekiL
hguorht gnitfis erew taht swalc elttil dna sgel ynit eseht lla ees dluoc ew htaenrednu tub
.gnimraf ,ekil ,ot od dluow taht tahw gnisseug
yrtnE *** nlaF— .suoiruf gnieb me dna desucof gnieb me dna teiuq gnieb me neewteb ecnereffid eht llet t’nac I dna
*** ].OPI lufsseccuS a rof edutitarG ni
.oot ,degnihnu elttil a gniog m’I deirrow m’I
.peels ot tsuj s’ti fi nevE
,wons yltcaxe t’nsi dnuorg ehT
.emit tub retsnom oN
fi suoregnad eb tcaf ni dluow dna retnec eht drawot sesaercni ti taht tbuod t’nod I
enO eerhT pelA waT telaD yrtnE *** nlaF dna druM—
,woleb tuo daerps tnenitnoc a fo flah elohw siht s’erehT
.rednuoF dna OEC
:sraeppa sseug a ,dnim s’redaer eht ni tuB
?noitacilbup elbissop
.pan a daH
!uoy knaht on
.elbasunu llits stnemurtsnI
?won tahw ,oS
.llew sa dehcatta taht dnif esaelp tub
.ereh si deulav gnihtoN
,suoicerp
.edarg-snopaeW
,krad neeb t’ndah ti fi kced retuo eht morf ti nees ev’dluoc ew
,elbaecalperri siht dah I elihw hctaw ot tog I tesrats yna fo evorppa d’I yaserad I tuB
.gninnur tfel I tnemirepxe tnerruc eht morf elbarevocer eb ot devorp atad fo revils ynit A .lla retfa
nlaF dna druM—
.gnihton llits ytilibisiV
.dednal tsrif ew erehw tnenitnoc emas
.yhw sseug nac I dnA
,gnidoorb
.gnidnaL noomyenoH no thgin tsaL
,adazO fo
?leber eht ro tnemhsilbatse ehT
.me fo eutats a edam yeht yhw ro ,saw siht ohw eulc oN
.noitces raelc eno saw ereht tub
.krow ruoy tsuj toN
,daeh sye fo kcab eht gnihctaw fo erom yna ekat t’nac tsuj I
gnikam‘ snaem ye hcihw yb
ecaf dnuor a htiw niht dna llat gnihtemos was I nrows ev’dluoc dna pu dekool I ecnO
.tnetsisni yrev
!taht etirw t’noD !srotsecnA
.knurd elttil a dnA .desaib m’I ,detnarG .elbidercni saw tesrats ehT eniN kemaS eH yrtnE *** )detcader yllaicifitra neeb evah egami siht fo snoitrop taht detceted sah metsys :ETON( gepj.gnirad_woh_drum
.ti diova ot ,ti nuhs ot enoyna erew ereht fi neve dediova dna dennuhs eb dluow ecalp sihT
.won ereh ton er’yeht
yllatnemercni fo snoitacilppa luferac yrev htiw detavitca eb dluoc ti fo emos kniht I dna
!repap fo steehs
.detsal ti elihw ,noitcartsid ecin a saw hcihW
.derimda ro ,raed dleh enoemos taht enoemoS
.041003210000.NACS
.dehcatta dnif hcihw
,spukooh tenalp detrahcnu tuoba seirots ynam oot
.lufwa sllems tI
,yawa secap derdnuh a tuoba saw tcafitra ehT
enO oreZ pelA yrtnE
.elpoep eht fo tsal ehT
.thgirpu saw ti llit ees t’ndid ew hcihw
.gnirad_woh_drum
nalF dna druM—
daeh ym ni tuo dennalp oiranecs …elohw siht dah I
,evila yllautca s’taht tenalp a no
.lufwa gnikcuf sllems mrots eht
.htaed fo regnirb a tub
.noomyenoh reporp a uoy ewo I dnA
.tsal tA .detcartsid
nwoner dna egdelwonk no seye sah eno ehT
.gnidnaL noomyenoH
.detsefinam sah tneve lacigoloroetem ereves a
.uoy htiw serutnevda evah ot detnaw I
htuom sti saw taht ebyam ro
ll’ew ,gib yrev ton s’tI
.eb yam ti revetahw hturt eht skees dnA
,shtilonom eht fo retemirep eht ta elbarudnenu tsomla s’tI
.syas ti revetahW
!ti nees d’uoy demussa I
.esimorp I seY
.mrots eht tub gnihtyna llems t’nac ew esruoc fo dna
.efas si roiretni eht dna
.slammam ylbaborP
.ebyaM ?noitaidar eht saw ti ebyaM
elihW —hcraes ni emac yeht srats detnuah eht ssorcA
,orez raen si ytilibisiv lanretxE
.pihs eht rof ekam ot gniyrt
.dab sa t’nsi llems eht tub
.trid eht ni egasiv tnanmer derettahs fO
,seirtne gol ym ni ti etorw neve I
,yltcaxe ,tenalp eht no tniop tsehgih eht si siht fi wonk t’nod I
,tiaw oS .daer gnieb erew yeht dekcehc ev’dluohs I
.noomyenoh reporp a evah ot
.oot uoy fo tser eht ees ot tnaw I tub
.tniop on eb dluow ereht tuB
,tcaf eht retfa deneppah meht fo htob ebyam rO
,elat siht no kooL
.rotacirbaf eht otni erawdrah ecafretni cisab ta sesseug emos demmargorp evaH
.dnal euqitna na ot srelevart owt tem eW
*** druM— .niaga tiaw tub od ot gnihton s’ereht won tuB
,reppoc dna nit fo yolla na
,tcatni yllaitrap eb ot smees tub ,edurc si edisni yrtiucric ehT
,deirt ew stiurf eht morf snemiceps dees eht gnigolatac si nlaF
,mrywkooB irikeneN​​ yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots sihT
.mrotsdnas evitcaoidar ylhgih A
.snialp eht
eht s’ti tub
.elpoep eht fo weiv eht morf ,elpoep eht fo noitatneserper A
.noissergga deyalpsid ro ,yawa nur s’gnihton tub
.hcnual rof gniraperp erew ew elihw ,srotceted noitaidar eht gniveirter morf kcab emac druM
,detpurroc ti fo tsom
,ereh ti dehcatta ev’eW
,esruoc fo
,kert a rof og ot stiusirips dedeen eW
’.seman pu
.ksa ot detnaw I
.renedrag a tsuj ton er’uoY
neveS niS telaD
!~pihs eht ni
.rehtegot sevil ruo htiw no
.etis gnidnal laitini ruo ta dnuof nlaF tcafitra eht
.oot uoy evol I …I
.detcepxe naht rethgil saw tI
.lamina dreh gnizarg yrotargim fo dnik emos neeb evah tsuM
…I dna tnednopsed demees yE
.erifpmac a rof doow gnirehtag si nlaF dna
.cillatem dna ,yvaeh
.gnihtemos dnuof d’ye diaS
.won pihs eht ot kcab gnidaeH
?esimorp uoY
evah ohw ,floWcaM boR dna lufraF lacsaP yb ”yawA raF hctertS sdnaL leveL dna enoL ehT“ fo
.su fo diarfa si tenalp siht no gnihton woh gnizama s’tI
.rekram evarg a eb llew yrev yam siht …tub
!ssalg lardehtac fo senap ekil sgniw dah tI
.ronoh fo ecalp a ton si sihT
*** nlaF— .sees druM erofeb taht eteled dluohs I
suoregnad eb thgim ti thguoht druM
.srekam erew yeht taht foorP
.aedi dab a saw taht wenk I tub
.gnidnal noomyenoH
.niaga ni dellor sduolc dnas eht nehw thgir nevorp saw I hguohT
?taht ot tpada dluoc yeht thguoht evah d’I
eviF pelA nijaZ yrtnE *** gepj.20amaronap_weiv gepj.10amaronap_weiv gepj.30skaepduolc
.segap yrruFoS evitcepser rieht no
!suoiruc tsuj saw ti tub
.egatlov gnisaercni
,neppah taht hctaw ot tog ew
,haey ,hcihW .skcor degrembus revo revir tfiws a ekil revo wolf dna meht tih
,abotinaM
.ecitsuj ti od t’nod serutcip ehT
?oot regnomraw A
.ti ot tsol mitciv
.hcum ton s’tI
neeb t’ndah ew fi
.smra ym ni peelsa gnitroppus/evitpecer/elam elbatrofmoc
,efil fo regnirb a tsuj ton emaceb noitaidar spahreP
pu gniyrrucs emac taht slamina elttil eseht lla yb dedavni erew ew
*** druM— .ereh kcuts eb ot gniog er’ew gnol woh wonk t’nod tsuJ
?shtilonom
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ecruos rewop a sa gnisu erew yeht gnihtemos eb dluoc tI
,stcafitra ro sniur dnim reveN
?…gnimmiws tuoba gnihtemos dias uoY
,kcuts llits er’ew elihw oS
,detam ylwen
,thginot srats eht rednu peels ot gnioG
…ot gnitrats m’I …tub
sduolc fo sknab nehw skaep eht ot yltcerid nezorf evah taht eci fo sreyal erom s’ti
,ereh pu thgin eht dneps annog toN
,druM ,od I .krow ym dekil uoy thguoht I ...ekil tsuJ
.tsal ta deerga ye dna ,edisni niamer ot me htiw dedaelp I
.20skaepduolc gepj.10skaepduolc
,erutainim a tsuj rO
,eb ot em detnaw sroines kcap ym sa lautirips sa reven saw I
.gniees neve ton er’ew gnihtemos saw ti dna
?enog erew yeht retfa pord naeco eht desuac dna ,tenalp ffo morf gnihtemos si noitaidar eht ebyam rO
ruoF niS telaD
teg dna ,tenalp nettogrof
.sgnileef rehto sah luos eht
.dnah ni dnah
nwod meht yal ot stnaw ylno rehto ehT
.su dnuora tib a deppord dah noitaidar eht
,mrots cimota eht ni wodniw ym edistuo was I noisiv taht ekil tol a dekool yehT
.sgnidliub eht sdrawot ni devoM
.etavirp erew yeht demussa I
htiw trats ot ereh dednal d’ew fI
.erofeb detsat reve s’ydobon taht stiurf citoxe yrt ot tsrif eht eb ot su detnaw I
gniraperp dnA
.deniatnoc ti peek ot ydobon saw
eerhT pelA teH yrtnE *** nlaF— !tsaf os saw tI
!dehsilop neeb dah ti ekil ynihs tub
,sgnidaer erom emos teg dna edistuo og ot detnaw druM
,ruoh na skcilc 061 fo deepsdniW
,tresed hgih
rennid gnixif elihW
,eno cilohocla taht gniworg yrt ot stnaw ye tub
er’ew nehw neve em htiw gnieb fo daetsni knuj htiw gnireknit dna spam revo gniruop er’uoY
.enog nehT
.haeY ?od uoY ~od I .yas ot tahw wonk t’nod I …I
.noitategev eht pu gniwehc dna dnas eht
.no gniog s’tahw tuoba stbuod evah
.noisorroc elttil ylgnizama
,ecived eht fo tnirptoof latigid etelpmoc a edam eW
.nlaF hO .hO .won pu meht gnillup m’I
.dalas tiurf ekam ot gniog s’ye syaS
.CLL ,retaW delttoB artsnelcA yb detcerE
,kcalb tsomla saw ti neerg krad os saw tI
,srotsecnA
,detseretni detca evah sgniht elpuoc A
!taert a rof gniggeb pu dedlof swap ekil
.10skaepduolc
.noomyenoh ruo fo otnemem a sa ,emoh ta flehs eht no peek ot
kcuf sa ypeerc esoht ni pu gnihtemos ekow dna dlrow daed a no dednal ew fi tahw ,ekil tuB
.muesum eht ta er’uoy nehw ekil tsuJ !pihs emas eht ni kcuts
,derettahs a morf snossel tuo esaet ot gniyrt tuoba tegrof eW
,elpoep owT
enO oreZ oreZ waT telaD
eulb a rednu selgnuj dna stresed
,elbaiv eb ll’yeht fi wonk t’nod eW
,eurt
!noomyenoh a rof ereh erew ew thguoht I
.emotipe s’evol ylluf rovas dnA
.emoh rof tolipotua tes dna ,syar ecnadiug enal eht deriuqcaer tsuj evaH
!seno toof xis ekiL
ll’ew pu swolb mrots rehtona fi os
.ereh dnuora erehwemos eb ot sah tniop tsehgih eht os
.ti fo ypoc nacs hsalf a edam nlaF
,lleweraF
.kool won
.oot ti ees nac uoy os
,nacs lluf a ekam ot thgirpu kcab ti tfil ot dah eW
.t’nsi ereht dnA
.emoh og ew nehT
,dnatsroV boB[ )swollof
.egami na s’erehT
,dias ye ,emit tsal enO
.evisorroC
,dnilb llits sgnidaeR
!did I etal ooT
,sgol eseht gnizinagro emit eht ssap ot gniog si druM
,llew sa ,esab eht no noitpircsni na saw erehT
.taen er’ew kniht ot mees tsuj yehT
.swap suortxed
.kcuF *** druM— .flesti htaed fo ecnesse eht ekil sllems tI
!su ot pu welf lamina eguh sihT
.sredaer ey
eht dna ,daehrevo eulb regnol on s’ti taht hguone niht nettog sah ereh pu erehpsomta eht
.nlaF dna druM—
:TNEMHCATTA ELIF
.deb ot emoc ot druM ecnivnoc nac I fi ees annoG
gniltsur ekil dnuos a edam sgniw sti elihw ereht gnirevoh tsuj seye eht ni su dekool tI
.spahrep ,ynomerec fo dnik emoS
.taert a sa ,krow elttil a evah dluoc ew dias nlaF
.30skaepduolc gepj.20skaepduolc
swap elttil etuc eseht dna seye eguh dnA
.ylerus ,ecnedicnioc a dna ,noitanicullah A
,lleW ?won tahW ?druM .edutilos tub regnad oN
.onnud I tuB
,haey ,yako… .em dlot ev’dluow uoy
,level cinaeco eht ot deneppah ylraelc gnihtemoS
ereht enog erew yeht retfa dna
,citats tub gnihton gniwohs era stnemurtsni eht
?tuo ti kcehc og ew nac
?deliaf secruos doof rieht ebyaM
.dnuof uoy rorriM eht ekam ot hguone decnavda erew yehT
,evael ,sessol ruo tuc dluohs ew fi gnirednow m’I
,ti daer t’nac eW
trats ot erehw wonk neve t’nod I dna
.ytefas noitirtun mrifnoc ot meht dennacs nlaF retfa ,ybraen stiurf fo seiceps lareves derehtag eW
yrtnE  2 fo 2 traP ,floWcaM boR dna lufraF lacsaP yb ”yawA raF hctertS sdnaS leveL dna enoL ehT“
meht tfel ye taht dnim t’nod I wohemos tub
.ytefas rof ekaM
,hoO .skniht etam ym tahw wonk ot tnaw I dnA
,txet fo laed taerg a s’erehT
.noitaidar fo sknits tI
.spahrep ,redael A
eht ni kcab
.yrros m’I dnA
yrtnE *** nlaF— !hgu edistuo dab os sknits ti dna dnim ym fo tuo deroB
.hcaeb reporp a no nwod tes eW
,pu ekow ew nehW
.melborp a eb ll’taht kniht t’nod I tub
.dnoces a rof tsuJ
,rorriM eht morf gnihtemos teg did eW
.ecno tsuJ
!elbidercni saw ti
,gnitloveR
.ereht teg ot hguone gnol seson ruo dloh dluoc ew
:yadot elat ruo fo larom eht si tahT
.muesum eht rof acilper a ekam
.taht sserper ot tseb ym
.wonk I .ereht s’ydobon syas nacs eht wonk I
?nlaF enO pelA waT telaD yrtnE
,lamron si ytirgetni lluH
.me rof tlef I
,yademos ,enoemos taht
,esolc eldduc ot evah
,meht daer ot em detnaw uoy fi tahT
,won si ti tahw ecalp siht edam msylcatac revetahw ni elor a dah ohw enoemoS
.dehsinif ton llits s’rotacirbaF
.kram s’rekam A
.mirg dekool yE
,pu stel mrots eht ecno sseug I
.gnivruc tenalp eht ees nac I raf os noziroh a ot yaw eht lla snekciht taht ezah
!ymedaca eht ta erew uoy nehw ekil tsuJ
gnimmiws og d’ew erehw
,devoleB ?deneppah yllautca kniht uoy od tahw os
dekool ti tub
.uoy evol I
.renedrag a tsuj m’I
:TNEMHCATTA ELIF
.kram A .seutats gnikam fo elbapac dnA
,lleW enO eerhT teB waW yrtnE *** druM— .sgol ym sdaer ye ,nevorp neeb sah sa dnA
!etam ym er’uoY
.noitidepxe siht gniunitnoc ot tniop yna s’ereht fi wonk t’nod I .lleW
efil tnegilletni tuoba stbuod on dah evah dluow I
.niaga tfarc eht tfel eW
,sgol ym gnidaer neeb ev’uoY
.tenalp siht no
.dnuorg eht no drawrof nellaf dah tI
.pihs eht gnirettab
,no gnaH ?tenalp siht deman I tahw wonk t’nod uoy snaem taht
,tsinoitidepxe eht er’uoy
.dnif ot ereh enoyna s’ereht eveileb regnol on I
.ti noitnem ot rehtob t’ndid wohemos tsuj ro nacs eht no taht dessim
.xaler ot ereh tsuj er’ew
.pihs eht fo kced retuo eht no sserttam elbadlof eht tuo diaL
yrtnE *** nlaF— .em ot gniklat ton s’druM
.haey …dna sfeirb ruo dehctid tsuj ew fi ees ot ereh ydobon saw ereht tuo tniop d’I neht dna
tahw… .yawa gnillup yb uoy no tuo taht nekat evah t’ndluohs I dna detartsurf saw I
,egnar niatnuom tsellat
.nwonknu ton tub ,tsol si eman s’tenalp sihT
sa stnetnoc( txt.041003210000.NACS
?tuoba klat ot tnaw uoy did
ll’ew …tresed evitcaoidar gniknits siht evael nac ew dna
,sbmil nihT
—dnah ni dnah ylwen
.thgilyad ni neve elbisiv era srats
,ezis gniyrav fo ,shtilonom naidisbo dekcap ylesned htiw derevoc si etis ehT
,mrots eht ni tuo ,liat on dna
a ebyam ro
.eciov a otni nrut ot gnitrats edistuo dniw eht raeh I gnikniht peek I
.ladepiB .sevlesmeht ot ekil dekool yeht tahW
.rettam taht rof druM sa ro