.gnittor yleugav dna tew
,dloc saw edistuo ria ehT .ti gnikcol dna
,esolc oot teg ot ton erus edam ahtnamaS
,noitelpmoc gniraen erew stset reH
,repap dna nep a pu kcip ot nwonk yllanoisacco si tub
,seye neknus dah tI
.rekaew gniworg gnithgif s'emong eht fo dnuos eht
,semong erom fo dleif a gnirevocsid ,dehcnelc stsif
.reh demusnoc ytisoiruC
llih eht pu kcab gnikool dna
tfil ot nageb gof ehT
,rettam fo selddup emaceb yeht litnu niap ni gnirehtiw dna gnilwoh ,tlem dna ynoga ni maercs ot nageb yeht
.emong eht no yltnenamrep eye na gnipeek ,ti gnitlob
,tuo dereep dna kcarc a rood eht denepo ahtnamaS
.od ot dah ehs tahw wenk ehs taht neht saw tI
,edistuo deppils dna rood eht denepo ehs
ekil ti morf efil fo mrof yna leper ot demees ti gnidnuorrus aera eht
,tekcaj a ni dalc saw dna
.spahrep wen dnarb tsomla ,naelc ...demees tI
,ffo etaropave ot nageb
.rood eht ot gninruter neht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,tey pu tuc t'ndah ehs snoino eht fo eno dna eno tsav a
,devom ehs sa reh dnuora sehsram eht dna stserof eht dennacs seye reH
.kcehc ot nwod tnew dna
.ssorc gnideelb eht ta
,reh dniheb dekool ehs ,ylevitcnitsnI
.edistuo dnuorg eht no teef elttil rieht fo dnuos gnirednuht eht raeh dluoc ehS
.delbuod etartraeh reH
,kciht a emac shtped eht morf tuo dna peed yaw eht lla knus edalb ehT
.hsac t’ndluoc rennam reh taht euqitsym rof seuqehc gnitirw kcalb lla eht ,erugif rednels ,trohs a tuc ehs ,eno yhs
dum fo level eht ot eud
.ti dnuora aera ralucric fo tros a nihtiw gniyd tsuj dna
.kcab spets wef a koot ehs
rood eht dehcaer ehs nehw gnippots ,esuoh eht sdrawot kcab gninnur
,enog d'ti erehw ees dluoc ehs tub
dna edisni teg ot emit on gnivah
,rood eht tsniaga mrof reh deliocer ahtnamaS .tsud
.reniatnoc eht fo sedis tew dna htooms ,yreppils eht no tuo bmilc ot ytiliba eht ton
,drayevarg eht ot tuo kool lanif a koot dna rood eht dekcol ehs ,yllaniF
,sniur enots fo stol ees dluoc ehs ksed reh yb wodniw eht morF
.seye nwo reh htiw ti was ehS .ereht saw tI
,ssorc eht morf kcab deppets ehS
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
bal eht fo thgis eht dnuora ssentnasaelpnu rehto dna
,toof reh htiw rood eht desolc ehS
ssom ni detaoc skcor suoirav
...taht naht erom ...tuB
ti hcaer ot gniyrt eagla ees dluoc ehS
.niaga gnipmuj dna rehtona gnikirts ,edis rehto eht ot gnipmuj
riah kcalb ,gnol kciht htiw flow yerg a saw ehS
...dekool tsuj gnihtemoS
,daeh reh revo edalb eht desiar ehs
rood eht nepo werht ehS
yaw esnesnon tub citsym emos ni
si yrots s’yadot dna
.detaretilbo neeb dah ssorc eht taht ees ot pu dekool
fo rewohs a ni gnidolpxe erofeb ,maercs gnilwoh ekil-eehsnab a dettime ssorc ehT
,ecalp siht ni tfel cigam yna saw ereht fI
.niaga emac skconk eht
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”ssorC dercaS ehT“ saw sihT
.ti ees syawla d'ehs eye s'ahtnamaS fo renroc eht fo tuo dnA .eno rof tpecxE
,bbe pot eht ta tih tnatsnoc a edam tlob eno erofeb ,ti ekirts ot deunitnoc gninthgiL
.srehto eht naht reraelc
.gnikool t'nsaw ehs elihw devom dah tI
.dnal hsram tfos eht ni peed dna
,dnif dluoc ehs gnixif dna gninetsaf fo mrof yreve htiW
.reh ta tuo pmuj ot ti tnaw t'ndid ehs tub ,sedis eht no deppots dah gnikconk ehT
.suoiciv dekool ti
.kcatta eht nageb dna
.od ot dah ehs tahw wenk ehs dnA
.nwod ti rettab ot ytiliba eht tuohtiw ,deciton ehs
.ti tuoba htaed fo hcnets niatrec a dah dna
.epacse t'ndluoc ti erus gnikam tsuj
,sessorc gnideelb citsyM ?ti dluoc
.sriatsnwod efas eht ni ti desacne dna edisni ti koot
,lanoitarepo tub nekahs
.sehsa dna srebme ot gninrub noos
.htworg fo mrof yna dekcal
...reh dekcatta taht semong
,eelf ot nageb ehs ,tniop siht tA
.seert eht fo sgniltsur eht otni dedaf smaercs rieht dna daed erew semong eht ,noos tuB
.ti dniheb llaw eht tsniaga gnirewoc dna
,napecuas eht ni eno eht derebmemer ylkciuq ahtnamaS
swap devolg rebbur reh htiw nwod dehcaer ylsuovren ehs ,noitarebiled fo os ro teunim a retfA
...rethgirb demees ti ...tub
.hsa fo elip eht rednu
,mlif gnilc ni xob eht depparw ehS
nap eht ni emong eht no dil a tup ot ssorca devom ehS .tsomla ...rethgirB
.t'ndluohs ehs wenk ehs ,t'ndluohs ehS
,tub ,rood eht ta gnirettab meht raeh dluoc ehS
doots ecno ssorc eht erehw morf tsud eht dna
thgin nmutua yggof dna dloc a saw tI
.sekops s'ti dnuora elcric a htiw ssorc egral A
,efink a koot ehS
,dnats ot desu ssorc taht erehw
.saw ti ereht dna
euqalp latem llams a gnilaever
,eciuj eht ni ti gnitaoc ,noino eht otni edalbefink eht knus ehS
,reifingam thgil a deniatnoc ylfeihc tub ,secived dna sloot suoirav deniatnoc tnempiuqe reH
.ekatsim reh desilaer ehs nehw niaga daeha gnikool dna gnikaeuqs
ti dleh swap reh sa xob eht gninepo fo tuo flesreh gniklat detrats ehS
.ssorc eht no llef seye reh
.ssorc eht dehcaorppa ehs sa
.suoremun erew yeht tub ,kaew erew yehT
.rehtegot gnikconk seenk ,deplug ahtnamaS
.enog saw emong ehT -ap eht ot nwod dna
,tsehc reh ot sdnah reh dehctulc dna
.ssorc eht fo pot eht gnikirts gninthgil fo tlob a yb maercs a ot deltrats saw ehS
,dnah ot dah ehs lla
elbissop sa emit fo tnuoma tsellams eht rof rood eht gninepo
,revo ti pit ot ssam eht evah t'ndid ti
taht ecaf ot evah dluow ahtnamaS
ot erehwon htiW .reh erofeb delbmessa dah ytnewt ekil erom ebyam ,net tsael ta
.ssorc eht ot htap eht pu dekool dna
,nwod decalp saw ti ecnO
,niaga emong eht ees t'ndluoc ehS
tfel eht ot dekool ehS
,ti ta kool ot gnirehtob ton ,nwod ti gnikcol dna
,ti erofeb doots ecnO
,neddir-ssom erew stelbat eht fo llA
.hsid irtep a ni scitoibitna
”ssorC dercaS ehT“
,sehctap ssarg deton seye reH
,erawanu meht hctac dna ylksirb dnuora pmuj ot gnivah
.nees eb dluoc ydobon tuB .nwod dna pu
...deniamer ydob reh sA
,seliM ennaoJ seil ereH"
,lufraF lacsaP  ecalperiF eht fo dneirF yb
.edisa depmuj dna
,pu ti dekcip dna
ecnef eht gnola kcab
nehctik tfihsekam llams eht otni ti devom ahtnamaS
.hctal eht dekcilf dna
rood reh dekcol neht
,delttes tsud eht ecno
.enileye reh ni yltnenamrep ti gnidloh
lufraF lacsaP yb
,ti ta gnirettab dna gnilggurts ti raeh dluoc ehs dna
,meht dehcuot pord a neve ecnO
,nwod eno gnikirts
.skrow reh no sucof dna dnim fo tuo ti peek ot dediced dah flow ehT
.sriatsnwod rood eht ta kconk a draeh ehs
.niaga tnereffid kool ot demees ti sa daerd htiw dellif traeh reH
.eye reh thguac gnihtemos ,gnineve taht wodniw eht fo tuo dekool ehs sa dnA
.egap ytiniffAruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
reh ediseb nwod dekool ehS
.erutarepmet hgih yltnacifingis a gnihcaer fo elbapac
,tsael ta gninialpxe
.nosiop eb ot ti gniraef ,yan ,gniveileb ,dnuorg eht ot llef dna ti deppord ehS .dekeer dna
.emong eht htiw od ot gnihtemos dah ti decnivnoc
,thgir eht dna
.tor ot desu efil
.gniraperp saw ehs snoino dehsaw fo tav egral a ni thgir dednal dah ti
.won os ro htnom tsap eht rof enod dah ehs sA
.ylmrif ti no seye reh tpek ehs tub ,od ot tahw wonk t'ndid ehS
”ssorC dercaS ehT“:yojne esaelP
,niaga htrof pets ot detrats ehS
wolg ot detrats dah ssorc ehT
...tub srehto eht sa kcor krad fo tros emas eht fo edam saw tI
,rood eht ot kcab devom ylsuovren ehs ,lortnoc rednu emong eht htiW
.t'nsaw ti won tuB
,egacbir reh ta gnirettab traeh ,ereht doots ehS
euqalp eht htaeneB
.triks reh rednu sniol dna shgiht reh dna seenk reh ta tib ti dna
.draobedis eht no nwod ti decalp dna
.boj eht did hcihw eciuj noino eht saw ti tub ,nwod meht kconk erom ,semong eht tuc t'ndluow efink ehT
.ereht saw ydobon tub
.wonk ot dah ehs tuB
efink eht desaeler ehs
.daer ti "ssorC dercaS eht fo repeek
sdrawretfa yletaidemmi ti gnisolc
.reilrae dekrow dah efink eht htiw kcirt reh yhw
...nepo gnurps xob ehT
,"ylloj" tib tsael eht kool t'ndid tI .seno der
,gnikrow saw ehs elihw ,ecno nehw
,dedeen fi naelc ot ysae erew eseht gninaem
...laer eb yllaer dluoc siht fo enon on on
.snoitca reh ot secneuqesnoc yna rof dnuora gnitrad seye
.ereht ni deppart saw ti os ,saw emong eht naht repeed saw lwob ehT
,yks eht otni pu gnitfil
,rood eht tuo gnikooL
,reh hcuot dluoc ti erofeB
,tnemezama reh oT
ylniatrec ,teiuq A .llew sa elbatrofmoc yrev meht dnuof ehs sulp
,edisni depacse dah enon taht dekcehc ehS
,delppot gnieb tuohtiw llams os gnihtemos thgif ot tluciffid saw tI
depmuj ehs ,edisni kcab og ot dnuora gninnips nopU
.ssorc eht fo kcen eht otni ti degnulp dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.thgir sti ot eno lanif a dna
.xob elttil emos won dna
teef reh ot tog ehS
,elbissop sa nepo tnuoma tsellams eht dna
srehto eht htiw ylcitameht tif ot demees ti tub erutcetihcra no trepxe on saw ehs ,eruS .ti tuoba gnorw
.ti dehcaorppa ehs sa efink reh fo edalb eht ot eciuj noino eht deilppaer ehS
...noino ydluom a naht erom elttil saw nihtiW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ecnayonna dlim reh ot
.xob eht gninepo dehsinif ehs
.yrotarobal reh ot gnidnet saw ahtnamaS dna
.nepo dil eht gnignilf dna sgnot emos gnibbarg
gnitoof reh gnidnim
.dnE ehT   …gninrom eht ni
...oN   .xob llams a saw
.nap eht fo mottob eht edisni diuqil yegduls a otni devlossid yllacitcarp dah emong eht
reh dniheb rood eht gnikcol ,esuoh eht ot meht hguorht kcab nar ehs ,daeha thgiarts tub og
,emong a ,ecnef nedoow
.noitulop thgil on saw ereht erehw erehwemos ,strikstuo larur eht ni detacol saw tI
,rebbur kcalb ynihs dna thgitniks a fo edam lla ,stoob hgih-eenk dna triks a ,sevolg
yawa dekool ehs nehw nevE
tniop tfel s'ti ot rehtona neht
swap htob ni dehctulc
.degnahc dah erutsop s'tI
,naicisum dna retiusruf a sa emit sih fo hcum sdneps ohw
.euqalp eht daer ot nwod gninael
.egduls elprup gniliob
,tnemesumeb reh ot tub ,niaga sriatspu kcab og ot tnew dna rood eht desolc ehS
.oot reh ot ti did ti esac ni tsuj
.kool peed a gnikat dna ediw ti gninepo emit siht ,rood eht ot denruter ehs fpmuh a htiW
.esolc oot ti ees t'ndluoc dna yawa raf ylriaf tas saw ehs ,niaga tuB