”REPPORDSEVAE EHT“
.nekops uoht tsah ylriaF“
ecalp taht ni ot klat dluoc eh taht rehto on saw ereht rof
.maerd dna enid ot won hsiw dna
hsram eht teem stresed eht erehw
,meht rof evol s’nerepsuN saw suoetnelp os roF
.sdnas eht yb deflugne
ti tliub dah eh sa tsuj
,u’oT dellac ecalp eht ot denruter dna
ylimaf sih nopu yllanif gniypse
doirep gniveirg eht ssap nerepsuN taht desivda yeht
.htrae ot dnecsed snevaeh eht nehw
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,secalp emas eht ni elpoep owt ot htemoc reven hcihw
,nem dna stirips dna sdog fo sgnilaed eht ni hteusne tahw evresbo ecneht dna
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb
pmac edam nerepsuN
,rehtie mih dnif ton dluoc htaed tuB
.htaed rof gnihsiw sdnal eerht eht derednaw eh os
siht fo esuaceb si ti dna
.ssima thguan dnuof tub
,peels sih ni mih ot emac ,ytip gnikat
,nemabeN fo nos ,nerepsuN dellac reyalkcirb a saw ereht woN
”.gniwonk
selpmet rieht ni deriuqni yeht nehT
,nioc yreve dna riah yreve detcepsni dna
.sterces fo dog eht dna dog terces eht
htob mih llac ew taht
pam on no hteil hcihw ,u’oT
hgin tlewd ohw sdaorssorc eht fo tirips a tuB
.edis yht yb erew yeht fi sa meht nekraeh dna meht dloheb uoht tlahs rennam siht ni ,ylireV“
deimyts erew sdog eht nehT
gof nwad eht ni tpecxe eno-
,llits hteniamer latrom a sa dereffus eh niap eht rof
,elcyc sruoH fo mooL lluf eht gnidulcni
”?evres ti htod esoprup tahw dna
.htrib morf mih yb desselb neeb htah
on ot hteraeppa dna
fo stsohg eht htiw
;daed eht
,eniw htiw seugnot ’sebircs rieht denesool dna stekram rieht ni deklaw dna
evoba sffilc eht morf deruop revir eht erehw
,modsiw rieht ni dna
.rof mih derimda dna devol yeht hcihw
.etipser mih reffo dluoc emitsap ylhtrae on taht
,nwad ta thgila dna
.dnal eht ni sgnag noitcurtsnoc dna srerobal eht lla fo dnammoc nevig saw eh dna
htaed otnu nekat htah ssenlli mohw
yojne esaelP  .xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb daeR  .3OA no
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
raf delevart evah ew rof
dnal eht ni erew ohw
- dnal eht ni toofa si ssenddo emoS“ :dias yeht dna
,dna ,tnemevaereb fo brag sih deipse
dellac ecalp a si
,luos sih deppirg sseniraew daerd nehT
:dias nerepsuN  ”.daed
devaereb ylwen esoht dnA
hcammaS fo sesao eht morf sdnal eht lla delevart yeht tsal tA
.redro ni eb ot tey deraeppa lla dna
,deraps saw nerepsuN hguohtla dna
- thgis a eeht wehs lliw I dna ,ot oG“ :gniyas
.mlaer siht retne yam I woh
”reppordsevaE ehT“ saw sihT
.ton erew rethguad dna efiw sih
awlA fo modgnik eht llac ew tahw nI  rettiR yb
.mlaer sih ni esahcrup dnuof enon tub
.enodnu emoc sdlrow eht ,ecilam ro
.peew dna liaw eh did yltaerg
,niatnuom rieht no gnillewd ,sdog eht tuB  .sdog dna nem fo
stonk evitcelletni lla htevaelc hcihw
,smegatarts fo rennam lla detpmetta eh taht dna
”.ecneserp s’eno fo erawa emoceb yeht taht tuohtiw
,u’oT dellac ecalp eht ni devirra noos eh rennam siht nI
.sdeer eht nopu dehcaorcne senud eht dna
,sgnidnuorrus sti ot ekila htemees dna
;emit rieht erofeb
”reppordsevaE ehT“ si
gninetsil er’uoY
.tsegnorts saw nus eht erofeb
:dias sdog eht dnA
,ssarg fo edalb yreve dna elbbep yreve gnitnuoc
nek latrom dnoyeb thguoht fo seitlucaf htiw nrob si ohw eno dna
,daed eht fo dnal eht otni thgis-ni sih nevig era
ytiralc neddus hteviecer ohw eno taht nwonk si ti os dnA
;dlo fo sgnik eht yb derovaf saw ohw
tniop eht htekram ti taht evas
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,esiwekil od tonnac yeht tuB
,seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,muxA fo sllih hsul eht ot
.gniwonk ruo tuohtiw su llafeb ydegart a tsel
.tnemrot emas eht yb
.nem dna sdog fo hcaer eht dna thgis eht fo tuo dessap dah eh rof
,emit eht ssap ot ytivitca on dna
;sbmot layor eht ni deirub eb ylimaf sih taht deerced dna strofmoc lla htiw mih dehsival gnik eht hguoht
,nerepsuN yb detisiv neeb htah
nerepsuN htiw ecalos kees ohw
yrots s’yadoT dna
,sdlrow neewteb dlrow eht otni ssap yam eno erehw
,nem fo dnal eht ot
.daed desselb eht fo
,u’oT dellac ecalp eht si siht rof
telmah edisrevir a dnuof eh ereh dna
uoy rof daer ,rettiR yb
,gnik eht dna sdog eht fo ronoh ni tliub eb ot selpmet ynam dna
:deilper tirips ehT
.daed eht fo dlrow eht ni tseeb oot uoht sselnu
thgis eht morf ssap nerepsuN did suhT  .maerd sih ni
yvaeh gnuh ria eht dna ,modgnik eht hguorht tpews ecnelitsep a ,raey eno tuB
,akazaM ot abaS morf smodgnik eht lla otni tnew yeht nehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,rethguad dna efiw ym fo emoceb htah tahw wonk niaf tsom dluow traeh ym tub
.erutaretil rof noissap a htiw yksuh lacisum a si ohw ,rettiR yb
,dnal eht deduorhs thgin nehw ,sgnineve eht ni pmac dluow eH
:dednopser nerepsuN dnA
,nrael yldalg dluow I nem dna sdog fO“
,nruom eh did yltaerG
.mlaer emas eht ni eb ot deen eht tuohtiw
:dias sdog eht dnA
,meht ot hgin tniop niatrec a ot tirips eht dewollof dna maerd sih ni esora nerepsuN oS  ”.mlaer
,eh saw yppah rof ,siht raeh ton did nerepsuN tuB  ”.maerd
smodsiw eseht trapmi ot woh osla denrael eh dna
.sepols eht nopu tliub dah nerepsuN hcihw emarf-rood eht deipse yeht
enutrofsim hguorht tsel
,og dna ecno ta ti dnema su teL“
:dias sdog eht dnA
.thgin eht rof detser dna
.snevaeh eht otni htewolf htrae eht erehw
emarf-rood eht doots ereht :ol
,edoba yldog rieht ot dnecsa ot tuoba erew yeht sa dnA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,erutan ro eman eurt sti gniwonk ton dna deiraeW
,em tsewehs uoht dna ,tirips ,neht og su teL
;dniknam morf dlehhtiw dah sdog eht hcihw egdelwonk hcum deniag eh
,awlA fo elpoep eht rof srednow ynam detaerc osla dna
,egalliv sih ot yaw edam nerepsuN oS
,etagitsevni su tel
,nem esiw sih morf lesnuoc kees gnik eht did suhT
,gof-nwad eht ni dehtaerw
siht si teknirt tahW“
desiar eb ot seutats ynam desuac eH
,sgniog dna sgnimoc rieht dna sgnilaed rieht dehctaw dna sdog eht fo emoh eht ot kcab tnew eh oS
,em ot raed erew yeht rof
;ton wenk yeht gniht a yb debrutsid erew
.brag s’rewodiw a gninnod dna yeknod a ylno gnignirb
,rewsna hcus on dnuof eh hguohtla dnA
emarf-rood a ekam nerepsuN edab tirips eht nehT
,u’oT nruter ton dluoc eh nehw nerepsuN dellif egar ythgim a taht dias si tI
,sffilc eht morf hsarc srevir eht dna
,seye latrom morf neddih eil tsum dna
”.meht tuohtiw thguan si efil ym dna
denedrub eb nosrep on taht
.secalp neewteb ecalp eht evael thgim eh woh nrael thgim eh taht
maes eht si ti roF
,ekowa eh nehw dna
,nem dna stirips dna sdog fo sdlrow eht rehtegot htednib hcihw
nerepsuN woh si siht roF
”.esuoh ruo no hteet rieht nettehw taht ecim rof eloh a spahreP“
,su ot sdog eht fo sterces eht htegnirb
.seiromem derusaert sih fo secalp eht ni
,egalliv eht fo sniur eht morf senots-gnidliub ro doow derrahc eht gnisu
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ssima thguan dnuof llits tey
hterised eh dna