;seirots recnaL ruoY sih tuo kcehc ,seires a ni detseretni er’uoy fI
.noisicerp dna ecnedifnoc htiw emac psarg sih
?naem rehtegot tneps emit ruo seod tahW“ ”?huH“
.ega on sah yrevocsid fleS
.terces ni rehtegot emit gnidneps nageb I dna oduL
.desufer tsuj eh ,tsrif ta
,sselnoitom os emoceb dluow eh denigami reven I tub
.ekaw sih ni spordraet fo liart a gnivael ,yleerf nar eH
;niaga evol nac uoy tahT
.em ot gnirepsihw erofeb ,dehgis ehS
;flesmih sserpxe ot syaw nwo sih dah raeb eht
”.rewsna thgiarts a evig t’nod uoy fi ton
;taht dnatsrednu I dna
.retsis ,uoy knahT“
…kniht ot emit erom em evag su dnuora erutan gnikaw eht dnoyeb ecnelis eht ,sseldrageR
,feirg fo nedrub eht tuohtiw taht mih gnidausrep
.yoj fo ecart a tuohtiw raeb nrets a sa ffo emac oduL
.kcab mih dessik I ,noos
.yaw wen a ni rehto hcae yojne ot werg htob ew
!mih llet ,mih llet ,mih lleT
,sraey owt tsrif eht roF
,tuB …uoy hsup ot tnaw t’nod I
,xes evah did ew semitemoS
.sih ot htuom ym sserp ot nihc ym depsalc eh ,dnah eerf sih htiw dna
nihc eht yb mih ekat dluow I erehw enecs a enigami em edam noitarepseD
ecaf ciots yllausu sih dnif ot ylkciuq denrut I
.dednuos eh tnatsid woh fo kniht ylno dluoc I
,htnom eht revo roivaheb sih gnirebmemeR
,thgir saw esiuoL
,rebmuls ot detfird I sa ,tnemom taht tA
.ytinifni taht egnellahc ot htgnerts eht dnuof raeb eht ,tey dnA
.tnurg gnivorppasid a htiw sworb gninworf reh desserp ehS .kcab derumrum I
.stur sih gnirud dereffus ylereves ehploduL ,gnissap s’efiw sih retfA
.yllautneve ,deppots eW
”.naem uoy tahw ees t’nod I“
,ffulb taht fo egde eht yb thgir
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ni gnimoc srelevart fo tes rehtona deciton I erofeb emit emos em koot ti ,desufnoC
yad eht eb yam yad yna
,neht tub ;sdnoces evif rof em koot noisufnoC ”?oga sraey net
.repsihw a ni dias I ”,oG“
.srats fo aes sseldne na erofeb evarg krad reh ees dluoc I dezilaer I ,noitisop taht morF
odibil ni esir esnetni na teg ot dnet sraeb tsom ,raey yrevE
.gninrom ylrae fo ria ypsirc eht otni deppets raeb egral a ,esuoh krad eht morF
emos …lavitseF tsevraH taht rebmemeR .si ti ,seY“
.thgin lla rehto hcae gnihcuot tuohtiw ereht peels t'ndluoc ew
fo tros eht ;tnemom taht denigami dah I ,sraey roF
.niaga rennid hguorht sseldrow deniamer eW
.doog naht mrah erom od dluow ytimixorp hcus deraef I
,mra eno htiw ydob ym dnuora flesmih depparw
,emit siht lla em ot lufrednow neeb evah uoY“ ”…oduL“
.ecnecsinimer ym ekorb gnileef fo kcal neddus A
.kcab delbmurg eh ”,seY“
.taht dednim reven I dna
na htiw deilper eh tub
”.yllautca ,yad llA .detcartsid
”,taht htiw laed ot emit thgir eht si pirt siht …kniht t’nod I“
,uoy rof drah si ti wonk I“
,em dniheb kcuns eh ,leips ym gniruD
.rehtaf retteb a sa tca dluow eh
thguorb ylno dah ew dezilaer ew nehw deifisnetni ylno ti dna
.elzzum sih depacse
gniliec s’tnet eht morf delf ecaf siH
.ecnalab gniniager retfa dias I ”!oduL“ .tnelis dna
,peels em tel ton did noitautis ehT
gniklat emos retfA
,ssik reven ot tseuqer sih ,sdrow nretS
”?naem taht seod tahw“
.thgilp ym derahs esle enoemos ,yllufknaht tub
,tserof evisnapxe eht fo elohw eht was ew
”,esiuoL ,uoy knahT“
ekatsim tsethgils eht ,dnim ym nI
.sthguoht ym lla niartser ot gniliaf
.mih ekorb tsomla sdrow yM ”.gnitiaw s’ehS“
.ma I“ .delbmurg eH
,delims ylerar eH
,knurd su edam dah erised ruO
,od srevol ylno sgniht enod evah ew ,xes dnoyeB
”.yllautneve nwo ruoy no ereh emoc dluow uoy niatrec m’I .enif s’tI“
.uoy htiw siht ekil gnieb peek ot tnaw I“
,yteixna lufdaerd yb deL
”.uoy rof ton ti fi og neve dluow ehploduL tbuod I .yats nerdlihc eht gnittel rof dnA“ .deilper I
,tpmetta ym ekilnu
.su neewteb hcni na ylno htiw em deppots ecneicsnoc yM .em rof evol sih sevorp yllanif dna ylurt oduL ym sa
,ylohcnalem htiw dellif llits enot a ni dias eh ”,nosmaS“
.denruter gnignol deniap tahT
.dnim ym fo sllah eht hguorht dewolf drow ehT .etaicerppA
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.gniklat tpek oduL tub ,tsetorp ot deirt I
.edialadA rof gnipeew ni mih denioj I dna
,mih ot txen deil I sa
,siht morf erom tnaw I ,oduL
,yltsal ,dna ,seert eht hguorht gnirehtils ezeerb dlim a ,tserof eht fo amora pmad eht
.elims deifsitas a htiw sezalb gnicnad eht ta dekool eh ,em morf ssorcA
.dereviuq htuom ym
.dedeen eh erusolc eht mih evig dluow—
.egalliv eht fo egde eht ta esuoh s’dneirf ym edistuo doots I dna
.rewsna na fo worra
,ekops I ”,enif m’I ,oN“
,tnelis denrut gnipoc ruo emit eht yB
.tuo su erit ot ytivitca tnasaelp
.em ecaf ot ehploduL detpmorp hcihw
ssenderit fo xim etuc a ni
,em ediseb ni thgir klaw mih gnihctaw ,neht nevE
”.em ot tol a snaem sihT
,emahs yb dnuobnu yllaniF
ni eugnot sih democlew I
.tserof eht otni evod dna daor niam eht tfel ew
.egreme ot ruoh rieht gnitiaw
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.hgiht ot tsehc morf rehto hcae tsniaga dehsurb ew
,wollof dluow esuap lufthguoht ,gnol a detcepxe I
,enim ot esolc os ecaf sih htiW
,tnemeticxe ro noitale tcepxe ton did ylerus I
.nem sdrawot seitivilcorp ym tuoba wenk sgnilbis raeb eht ylno os
,elims tsethgils eht dna smuh lanoisacco sih yb ylnO
.em revo koot gninraey elbarelotni dna niap prahS
,kniht ot emit erom emos mih gnivael llitS
;dnuorg eht otni enim tneb ydob sih sa tsriht ym deifsitas I
”…gnissap s’edialadA
.dnuorg eht ot em dekconk ylraen dna edirts ym detlah yltpurba
.tuo emoc ot etal oot sa gniht hcus on si erehT
eman a otni desnednoc efil a ,ti no dna
drawrof yaw taht dnif ew taht
,tnatsni na ni dedaf ezad yM
.em dehcaorppa spets sduol
.enim htiw sregnif sih gnikcolretni yb dednopser eh ,dne eht nI
.pets tsal taht ot tcejbo ot erised gnorts a htiw dereviuq pil rewol siH
detapissid nevaeH
;enim rof dehcaer mlap nwo sih ,hgis a htiW
,snoitpo rof gnikool dna gnitsetorp deirt I oS
,sraey ni emit tsrif eht rof ,eman reh demaercs eh sA
noitcafsitas dnif ot flesym gniwolla ,kcab werd I
,ti pots ot drah os deirt esiuoL dna uoY
.detrons eH ”?reh tuoba ti sI“
klat mih edam reve dah I tsom eht—
,slisnetu desu eht yawa gnittup dna gnitae dehsinif ew retfA
…yteixna elbarelotni htiw
”?retteb yna leef uoy oD
gnikaeps erofeb smra sih ni elbmert I
.ssenkrad eht ni noixelpmoc ym gnidih ,esor I
,kcab dloh dluoc I erofeB
…tub siht ksa ot ecalp ym ton si ti dnatsrednu I os
”.tser dluohs uoY“
.seye ym depacse sraet ,evoba srats eht ta gnikooL
hsiugna htiw detaslup traeh yM
.ssenkrad otni repeed flesym gnignulp
.sdnalssarg gnidnuorrus eht fo weiv cimaronap a ot detaert erew ew sa ria nepo ot yaw evag dnaldoow esned ehT .rehtegot ,sdrawrof deklaw ew ,os dnA
.noitautis eht ssecorp ot dedeen eh ecaps eht evag dna
.ecnalab elbatrofmoc a ni
,denruter gninraey lufniap ehT  .luferac dna
,relevart wollef ruoy
.ylsselemahs decarbme ew nehw sthgin nezod a fo yromem eht denommus taht gnileef a
retfa dna erofeb ,em rof enod evah uoy gnihtyrevE
,god.ecioveht ta
eno denruter sesnes yM
.elbaplap emaceb mih no dah pihsnoitaler wen ruo tceffe eht ,emit taht gniruD
,detniop enisru eht erehw tnew ezag yM
,moordeb eht edistuo rehtegot emit hcum os tneps dah ew ,emit driht eht yb tub
,esle gnihtyna tuoba deirrow I erofeB
”,mih lleT“ .ekops osla tub
.nwo ym htiw elzzum sih otni evod dna
.lareneg ni nepo erom dna
.llew sa sdnah sih ni em sekat eh
.erised emaceb noitaroda sa dedaf nirg derit yM
ticile dluoc yromem esohw nosrep eno ylno s’ereht
.detnaw I tahw hcaer ton dluoc sdnah ym tub
.tleb ym dnuora slehctas eht htiw delggurts I woh nevig
,ecnatsid eht ni raf ,dna
.hcti no elbaliava
,tuokool eht no eb ,esiwrehtO
llordeb sih gniodnu nageb eh ,nooS
;roirp keew a pirt eht mih dereffo dah I
,dnim ym no gnihtyreve mih llet dna
,gninrom gnipoleved eht hguorhT
”!reh gnidaog tpek I tub
”.detfil neeb sah ylniatrec thgiew a tub
.sthguoht ym deppots ,htuom s’rentrap ym morf noitamalcxe ypsar a ,dnuos ffurg A
tnelis deniamer enisru ehT
.ytiraluger emos htiw etalupoc t’nod yeht fi—tur a sa nwonk—
.noixelpmoc deirrow a htiw em desserdda ,norpa ytrid dna sserd wolley dedaf a ni dalc ,raeb-ehs egral A
;railimaf yltcefrep werg ecalp eht ,dnuora kool a retfA
,lausu sa syaw nwo ruo gniog dna gnisir fo daetsni ,riaffa ruo dedulcnoc dah
”.won elihw a rof leurg ruoy ta gnikool neeb evah uoY“
.sraey esoht revo ssecorp gnilaeh sih ni emoc dah eh raf woh eveileb etiuq ton dluoc I
.yojne ot werg I syaw
”?thgirla uoy erA“
gnidrow tcefrep eht detcocnoc niarb ym fo trap yreve sa em tceffa ton did osla laem ehT
.hgis ythgim a deffuh ehploduL
,diulf eb nac ytilauxes dnA
.deen a sa nageb tI
,daerd ro snoitagilbo
.deniamer I dna oduL ylno litnu
.kcab kool ton did tub ,esir mih draeh I ”…maS“ ”!su morf
.aelp tnelis ,dimit a ni sih dezarg dnah ym ,ti pots dluoc I erofeB .gninraey dna
;gnissap reh retfa yllaicepse
.sthguoht nwo ruo ni debrosba daor eht no yad eht fo tser eht tneps eW
”.wonk t’nod I …snaem tI“
”,yob-tac ,won peelsa thgir era yehT“
,sih tsniaga kcams spil ym raeh I
.siht rof uoy knaht“
.sraef ym esae ot deliaf taht eno ,plug a sa emac noitcaer tsrif yM
?rettam eht s’tahW“
.thgin taht noitilov nwo sih no em degguh eh yaw eht ni
.mih dnuow thgim troffe yna taht gniraef tub psarg nihtiw mih gnivah fo msahc eht ni kcuts flesym dnuof I
,derats ylno ton hsum dehcuotnu ehT
.sdnoces wef a rof thguoht peed ni flesmih tup dna dehgis ,detnurg eH ”.ma I“
.redaer evitcaretni na htiw dna koob a sa oi.hcti
dedaf flesti dlrow eht dna tserof eht ,sthgis eht ,sdnuos ehT
.tuo hcaer ylpmis t'ndluoc I dna
.dias eh ”,thgir era uoY“
.eunitnoc ton dluoc noitautis taht
.htaerb mraw tuo ssih elzzum gnirebmuls sih dehctaw I sa ecaf ym no demrof elims yllis A
.emahs dna yoj ,gninruom fo xim a ;su revo depard gnileef euqinu nA
egayov eritne eht detaemrep ssenisaenu gniregnil A
”.os od ot elba eb ot yad yreve krow ll’I esimorp I
.emit on ni tuo ti derugif flesreh esiuoL
,adA revo truh llits uoY“
,laer gnihtyna psarg ot gniliaf dnA
”.hcnul rof pots nac ew“
,mih morf gnimoc ees reve dluow I thguoht reven I sekil eht ,selffins dna sboS
;su rof gnidne yppah a ot dael dluow taht
.ecneliS ”?regnol elttil a
.noonretfa taht deneppah dah tahw gnigdelwonkca neve tuohtiw doof ruo eta ew
.em ot denruter oduL nehw
;em detavitpac syawla ecaf sih no ssenteews taht ,did eh nehw ,tuB
,reippah emoceb dna worros taht fo og tel mih was lla eW
,deb ni erew nerdlihc eht ,ydaer erew snoisivorp ehT
”.ti dedeen I wonk neve t’ndid I
.sdrow ym deffuns eh evom neddus ,elgnis a nI
.sdrow esoht dewollof esuap gnol A ”.dalg m’I“
.pu snepo drawrof daor wen a taht
.yas ot dah I tahw reviled ot yaw tseb eht detaluclac I sa
.ecnatsiser sih rof ecarg ed puoc a devorp dnekeew eht rof nerdlihc eht ni ekat ot ssendnik s’retsis siH
.tser ot delggurts ew
!adA ,yrros m’I“ .dias eh ”,adA yM“
.egnaro denrut dah yks noonretfa etal eht
tnaligiv niamer ot dah ew
.noitasrevnoc tsellams eht gnirahs setunim fo elpuoc txen eht dneps eW ”.esruoc fo
,sdne daed tub gnihton ,no evom ot yaw on yltnerappa htiw efil a ni nevE
delahni ylduol eH
,elkcuhc a retfa dias I ”,yakO“ .regnuh dna
.wob kciuq a retsis sih dereffo dna deffuh enisru ehT
.em ot raelc etiuq emaceb gnihtemos
tnet taht edisni ,retfa gnol toN
.ecaf sih ni yoj hcus
,etihw dna yarg fo xim ym gnipolevne ruf nworb ,hguor ,egral sih fo hcuot dna thgis ehT
.em sdrawot daeh sih krej ot mih evord noitca yM
”?neppah gnihtemos diD
,ssenteiuq fo sruoh retfa ,nehT
.tuo hcaer ot em degru ti
.ygiffe eht ot dehsur dna dniheb ograc sih werht enisru eht ,retal dnoces a toN
;mih ot degnoleb yenruoj eht
,tseuqer ruoy si taht fi tuB
.ssarg krad eht no denoops ew elihw osrot rewol ym degguh eH
.yad gniwollof eht sgnileef ym mih llet dluow I ,wohemos
”…I ,nosmaS .sdrow on evah I“
.sloot lufesu dna
reilrae sraey evif gnissap reh ecnis tsrif sih—
,yb dessap yeht sa seirtnasaelp degnahcxe eW
”.revoc ot dnuorg hcum evah eW“
,mih was ohw enoyna oT
.sruoh suoiverp eht tliuber yllaudarg dnim ym sa dedaf ezad ehT .ecaf ym no thgilnus nedlog eht ta desufnoc
;noitnetta ruo fo erom werd esle gnihtemos ,teY
gnihca eno sevael taht noitome fo tros eht
stoob rehtael tsubor ni levart rof desserd emac eH
.remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR yb uoy rof daer ,nagidraC yb ”gninraey lufniap ehT“ saw sihT
”?mmH“ .mih ta gnikool ,dias I ”?llew gnileeF“
sdrow dnasuoht a em dlot emarf sih fo noitanimaxe esolc a
.noitasrevnoc dehsuh ruo no dedurtni spets fo tes rehtonA
.ssarg tew dna sevael yhcnurc ot yaw evag daor trid ehT
,teiuq tnew eH ”?tac yeson a uoy t’nerA“
.tnet depmarc ,elgnis a
”,nosmaS ,og su teL“
”!won mih llet“ ,dias ti
krad enog dah sdoow ehT
.erif eht ffo seye sih gnikat tuohtiw kcab dias eH
.noisiced ruoy fo sseldrager dneirf ruoy niamer lliw I dna
.rehtob on s’ti ,oN“
.sgnileef esoht lla kcab dloh ot
,enola lla era ew nehw
,ecnatsid a morf elbmurc mih dehctaw I ”!yrros m’I
.enola noitaicerppa no gniog peek dluoc ”ew“ taht dna
.erujnoc nac smaerd ylno erutseg citnamor ,gib
,evitisnesni dna elbatrofmocnu neeb dah ecneirepxe elohw eht
sgnileef sih devorp stpmetta sih taht
.dnik ym sdrawot ytilitsoh eht fo em dednimer ylmirg retnuocne eht ,edisni tub
.rewsna emas eht htiw detroter tsuj raeb eht tub
,struh llits …tI .os kniht I“
llits gnidnats raeb suomrone eht
.mra thgir s’rehtorb reh no mlap reh gnittup elihw daeh reh koohs esiuoL
,tniopdnats lanretap a morf yrots eht emarfer ot dah yletamitlu I ,tnatsiser llitS
.ma yllaer I ,em etaicerppa ot dalg m’I“
?mmH“ .ezad a ni mih ta dekool I .dias eh
,sllordeb ruo fo htob rof ecaps hguone dah ti elihW
”,yas uoy raeh ot deen I
?gnivom ton eh saw yhw ,neht tuB
.rehto hcae ta derats ew sa deppots emit erehw eno gnol ,lufniap a ,esuap rehtonA
.aes taerg eht fo eulb etinifni eht
,reisae sevil s’rehtona eno gnikam yb ,stnemom eseht ni si ti tub ,gnitadimitni eb yam tI
”?erus uoy erA …oduL“
,seidegart ynam s’efil sih gniwonK
delbmert sdnah ym dna htuom yM
”-m evol uoy taht“
a tsuj ,gnigagne gnihtoN
.dnoces a rof aiglatson ni peed
.pirt siht tsuj tuoba gniklat ton m’I
,sehtolc decrofnier dna
…kool uoY“ ”?yhW .ma I
”.yrassecen eht“ tsuj naht erom od ot dediced ew—
trotnoc noixelpmoc sih dehctaw I
,ylpeed os sevlesmeht dessorgne sdnim ruO
.ekahs mih edam ,sraey rof kcab dleh raeb eht snoitome eht llA
:aedi taht deffuns noitazilaer a ,tuB
:noitulos a htiw mih ot emac I ,raey a retfa
.eruliaf suounitnoc ot del ,trapa rehto hcae peek ot stroffe ruo ,ylgnisirprusnU
.thguoht ni demmuh enisru ehT
,su fo tnorf ni seert fo elpuoc eht dnoyeb tsuj
,rennid kooc pleh ot dereffo eH
.riapsed otni gnitemmulp sthguoht ym ,dniheb deggal I dna ,del eH
.tpew dna enotsbmot eht erofeb seenk sih no llef eh
.daetsni htraeh gnimrahc dna yzoc a til dna
.elims a htiw deilper yllanif I ”,gnihton s’tI“
,wollef evitaklat a reven saw oduL
lla tub ,snrecnoc ym ehtoos ot tnaem eh ,mih gniwonK
,sllih dna sniatnuom neerg
,degnol dna truh eh
”?dnim ruoy no s’tahW .uoy no elims yllis a evah uoY“
.noitcif evitcaretni dna seirots trohs tluda setirw ohw ,nagidraC yb
.em dehsinotsa noitome eht fo ytireves ehT
,esolc ytterp pu werg eerht su ,mih esirprus yletelpmoc ton did tahT .em
detubirtnoc lla snoitome rehto ynam eht lla dna ,flesym ta regna ,terger ,emahS
.eruliaf fo tros emos ni dedne llits stpmetta ym fo lla
,yllanif ,litnu ehca eht denekaew
”–esrow eht ,yaled uoy regnol ehT
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.gniklaw ,deunitnoc eh
,sevael daed fo hcnurc eht ;eno yb
.niaga ecalp siht fo kaeps reven dna emoh nruter ot
.dnah ym fo og tel ylkciuq raeb eht deciton I sa
.daeh sih koohs dna deffuh eH
.od ot dah I tahw wenk I
,ylduol ,ylrednet ,ylippolS
.dehctiwt sregnif gnignah sih
”?sey ,erac ekaT .oduL ,lla ta toN“
”gninraey lufniap ehT“
”.elihw a rof pu eb t’now yeht dnA” .dias ehs
.heH“ .elkcuhc ot emit sih emac ti ,nehT
.sdnah ym ni lwob eht ot elzzum sih detniop eH
.rouqil tseteews eht dnuof ew htuom s’rehto eht ni dna
noisilloc a litnU
.yas reven dluow ehploduL
,selims dna snaorg ,ffuh fo elpuoc a morf edisA
:neht eciohc eht edam I
.enot suoires a ni ekops eh ”,tes lla era eW“
,ereht mih dediug dah I elihW
.elbissopmi tlef enecs suoegrog taht morf yawa kool oT
.ecneserp s’rehto hcae gniyojne yltnelis neve ro gnisrevnoc
.elims duorp ,ypeew a htiw dias I ”,oduL ,og s’teL“
.esnopser ni delims I
.raey a ecno rehtegot gnipeels nageb ew ,os dnA
,edis thgir ym no em dna kcab sih no miH
”?emit siht mih llet uoy lliw ,maS“
,mih dehcaorppa I
.deraperp dah I laem eht deyojne etiuq eh llet dluoc I
.pirt siht htiw pu emac I
,sezilaer eh ecno ,erehw enO
.niap nwo ym edih ot tseb ym gniod ,deilper I
.erusaelp ym s’tI“
,gnihtyna gniyas erofeB .em ekil tsuj
.ecalp gnitser reh erofeb thgir tnatiseh os
.deb ym no edis yb edis deregnil ew
.erif eht yb tas ylpmis ew
,sllordeb ruo ni dna
snoisivorp htiw deffuts kcapkcab a htaeneb dekcut lla
,dehsinif hcum ytterp saw ti tcaf eht dna noitautis eht nevig ,tub
,floWcaM boR si sihT
.dnim ym ni niaga dna niaga dnammoc eht draeh I dnA
”.ees I ,hA“ ”...yromem doog A“
.dleiy ot mih hsup rehtruf depleh
;em ot yaw sti edam ylisae
.noitanitsed ruo hcaer dluow ew
,snoitarebiled ni kcuts llitS
”.ereh era …eW“ .delahxe dna
.won thgir tnaw uoy sdrow eht uoy evig tonnac I yrros m’I
yb em dessap daor eht no tneps emit eht dna ,tsafkaerb ,gninroM
.detsefinam feirg nwo ym
,sraey eht revo denrael dah I sA
.yltcerid em tem yllanif dna
;ti gniod peek t’nac tsuj I dna
.noos wen gnihtemos pu gnikooc eb thgim eh
,pirt taht gnirud yllaicepsE
,hguorht tnew raeb gnirewot eht noitrexe eht enigami ylno dluoc I
.gnihtemos em llet ot
.nirg sih delaever ylerar eh enola stnemom ruo gnirud neve
…tsuj ew ,semit lufrednow ynam os tub
,gnipsag dna ytaews ,ew retfa ,thgin tahT
,yad taht retfa evarg eht detisiv reven dah eh em dlot retsis sih ecno ,dnA
em revo emac sgnileef fo yrrulf a
.ytilaer ot mih derohcna dna dnah gninraey sih rof dehcaer I
.pmac edam dna daor eht gnola seert eht ni gniraelc a derevocsid ew ,retfa gnol toN
,noissim ruo ekasrof ot mih gnillet fo thguoht I ,yllaitinI
,sraet ni mih dloh
”?ew era tahw ,oduL“
.sraet fo egrev eht ta em tup seye sih ni tnilg eht gniteem ylpmiS ”.gniyl era uoY“
!ahah ,eriF taerG eht revo pmuj dluoc ehs detsisni ehS !sey ,hA“
.sdrow fo lufdnah a naht regnol noitasrevnoc a gnirahs ton ,ylidaets deklaw ew
.tnelis erom dna redloc werg eh
.nevenu emaceb gnihtaerb sih
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,heH“ .elims yraet a otni spuccih htuom yM ”.oot ti detnaw …I“
.mih gnidnilb nus gnisir eht morf seye sih dedleihs raeb ehT
,trofmocsid dna gniltsur hcum retfa ,oS
.ecnelis luftsiw a otni nwod deid rethgual ruO ”…deedni
”,uoy dluohs os dnA“
.ehploduL gnirons a ot gniklat flesym dnif ot em rof gnol ekat t’ndid tI
.sdnoces fo elpuoc gnol-ytinrete na rof ecnelis elbatrofmocnu ni deregnil eW
.dnopser ot woh wonk ton did I
;em yfsitas ot enola drow taht rof demaercs dna deggeb I
,ahaH“ ”.sserd reh degnis ylno ti ,yllufknahT
”.uoy etaicerppa I“
.taht retfa gniog peek ot htgnerts ym fo lla koot tI
.eciov enotonom a ni revo dna revo dias eh ”,enif s’tI“
.seitniatrecnu fo yteirav a yb dednuorrus werg detnalp I hcaorppa yrevE
”.eromyna siht od tonnac I …tuB
,enim didnu eh ,noitseuq ot ecnahc eht dah I erofeb ,dna
,dnA .ton ma I ,lleW“
.tnet ruo pu tup dna daeha no tnew I
.sthguoht ym ni deohce
”!em gniretsep naht sniwt eht htiw emit erom dneps lliw sekyt ehT
.srepsihw ni klat ot em devom snoitome fo mrots a ,denruter nosaer dna
.su no ni tperc tesnus fo seuh egnaro eht
.llifluf dluoc su fo rehtien sdnamed diputs ekam
.yenruoj ruo fo hcterts tsal eht fo trats eht denimreted dliw eht otni spets ruO
.sgnileef ruoy em llet uoy raeh ot deen I tuB
,os ,tnetxe taht ot gnilggurts mih hctaw ot truh tI
;noisicedni sih rof noitanalpxe na rof gnikool
,I dna miH .deregnil
evarg reh ot tisiv a taht detsisni I ,teY
.noitautis drawkwa eht ni gniregnil ot detroser ew
,ecnetnes a etalumrof ot detpmetta eh llet dluoc I ,ecaf sih morF
.elffins a dniheb
.seye ym gnipacse sraet htiw ,kcab degguh yletarepsed I
;yoj dna edirp htiw em dellif mih gnieeS
”.neht ,og su teL
yojne esaelP  .remrahC eniuqE eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR  .rehtegot
”.ma I lufetarg woh uoy llet ot sdrow eht evah t’nod I .maS ,em evigroF“
peels …ot tnaw uoy oD“
.yenruoj taht gnirud ton
”gninraey lufniap ehT“
.erif eht yb rennid feirb a dah ew ,sseldrageR
em dnuora demrofer tserof ehT
.dnim ym edisni dna su dnuora htoB
,erif eht morf yawa denrut I sa
”?og ot ydaer uoy erA .won thgir yrgnuh yllaer ton tsuj m’I“
.em tsniaga elitsoh nrut ylbissop dna
.tniop ym dnatsrednu ot mih rof stpmetta eltneg fo elpuoc a koot llits ti ,os nevE
,htaenrednu sreyal detcepsusnu wen htiw
.deliaf I ,dne eht nI
,ekowa I  nagidraC yb
ssendloc s’dniw eht tsniaga dehsalc htmraw s’emalf ehT
.ezag gnihsulb ym teem ot denrut ylmlac enisru ehT
,sgnileef lufemahs dna detcirtsnoc esoht yawa denrub tlep enisru ,mraw tahT .ecarbme elbatrofmoc a otni rehtegot su dellup dna em dnuora smra yvaeh sih depparw oduL
,doots bals enots trohs a
,yraet emaceb eciov gnilbmert ym
tsuj em rof tiaw uoy dluoC
.elbaraebnu thguoht rehto yna ekam ot
,redluohs ym no daeh sih htiw ,dias I ”,oS“
.hgis a htiw denaorg eh elihw a retfA
,pirg nori sih depacse dnah yM
.waffug a htiw derebmemer I
,ffilc ydniw taht morF
.pu ekops raeb eht
.ti wonk uoy dna no og t’nac sihT .nosmaS ,sesruC“
,eveels ym no dellup dnah egral s’raeb eht ,ruoh na retfA
.em ta kcab gnirats klim dna laerec fo xim ypsar eht dnuof dna
.htuom suonrevac sih edisni eugnot ym egnulp dna
.tser lanrete reh deyojne ehs ,epacsdnal citsatnaf taht yb ,erehT .setad owt dna
,esrow noitautis eht ekam sgnileef esoht tel ton dluoc I tuB
.erom ecno ti ta ezag dna erifpmac eht dnuora tis ot eerf mih tfel tahT .denilced I
htmraw sih ,rehtael fo sreyal owt hguorht nevE
.degnahc pihsnoitaler ruo woh saw sraey esoht gnirud tnempoleved rehtonA .kcab depsarg I
,ereht thgir nwod kaerb ot detnaw em fo traP ”?rehtegot
,dehcaorppa htaed reh fo yrasrevinna rehtona sa ,revewoH
sdrow ym dnatsrednusim ot ehploduL esuac dluoc
.ria ylthgin eht ot sosrot ruo gnisopxe
.su pots ton did llaf eht dna
em htiw gnieerga dnabsuh reh dna esiuoL
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.eromyna delims su fo rehtien ,nooS