nomed eht denekawaer dna
.ecnalg gniwonk a htiw niatpac eht dias
,ecaps otni tnempiuqe riaper fo eceip a worht
.pit gnidlew eht mih dednah ohw ,flow eht ot revo deklaw feihC
.tnelis llef redlew eht dna
.llaw raf eht no gnignah draob eciton eht nopu llef seye sih nehw
,terref eht ecaf ot denrut eh nehW
.mih llik thgim boj eht taht gnitseggus nmuloc a neve saw erehT
.ereht tem evah ot demialc yeht elpoep desserd ylitnacs dna citoxe eht
fo trap lanif dna
ni derevoc saw draob eht yllausU
.roolf latem eht ssorca decnad ti sa gnikraps dna gnicra pit eborp sti
",gnol siht tsal ot mih tcepxe t'ndid I
,eriw eht detcennocer dorlE nehW
esruc dna lwoh ot deunitnoc flow eht sa
.esnopser eht emac
.sissahc sti koohs dna
loot gnipmirc eht dorlE dednah feihC ehT
---  .elims eht denruter feihC ehT
,eeffoc suocsiv eht fo pis txen eht yb yawa depiw ylkciuq saw
,IA na dna ,nem nworg eerht hctaw tsuj I diD"  .redneH saw
,syad owt ni trop hcaer eW"
.wonk t'nod I"  .geR deksa
.peels luftser emos teg ot elba yllanif erew sreenigne eerht eht
,rehtegot kcab siht teg uoy pleh em teL"
,egami s'ecnaL hguorht gnissap ,daeha nar geR
.tinu eht ot rewop llits saw ereht dna
nepo rood kcolria eht dah dna
.dorlE morf detpure gniraews fo evaw hserf a nehw evael ot denrut tsuj dah
,kcil a niats eht evig ot tuoba tsuj saw eh ,etarepseD
skcar rieht ni kcab seludom eht fo tsom dnuof eh ,yab eht deretne eh nehW
.IA eht deilper ",eciwt dereggirt neeb sah metsys noisserppus erif eht dna
.toof eno no gnippoh elihw
,yawyna regnif sih dessik tub
.detrats eh ecnis semit eerht ytnewt nepo ot deksa neeb evah srood erusserp niam ehT"  .geR deksa
.rehtegot setalp kced eht dlew ot gnitpmetta regnol on saw pit eborp eht tub
enimreted ot gniyrT
---  .krow ot tes nem owt eht dna ,deddon flow ehT
,yllacitsacras dorlE deilper "ecnaL ,sknahT"
.niatpac eht dias ",kcab ti tup woN"
",yadot retfa ti ot pots a llac ot evah ot gniog m'I ,ti od ot etah I sa hcum sA"  .denworf geR
.redduhs mih edam hcihw
'?dooF'  .eson sih delkcit llems a nehT  .noitartsurf ni
.ylmlac sa tsuj ,geR dias
,tcatnoc eht morf yawa emac eriw eht tnemom ehT
.eudiser puos derettalps ni
deksa "?ekam taht seod ynam woH"
.lausu naht rekciht ylbaeciton saw dna
.flesmih ot thguoht eh
.llaw eht tsniaga depmuls flow ehT  ".gniht ..sihT"
,kced eht otno stnetnoc sti fo emos gnillips ,syawedis deppit tub
flow eht dellup feihC ehT
.yab ograc eht otni kcab gnitnirps emac geR
,semit thgie tuo enog evah yab eht ni sthgil ehT
revo nekat neeb dah draob eht fo ytirojam eht woN
.peelsa si werc eht fo tsoM"  .denway eh
.mih ta delwocs nooccar eht
.gnivael eb ot yppah yleniuneg dednuos dna
maercs gnildruc doolb a evag dorlE nehw
,meht dniheb eramthgin gnol sedaced eht htiw ,thgin tahT
ssenrettib sti ta gnignirC
".noitidnoc lanoitarepo ni kcab eb ot yab ograc taht deen I dna
.yawyna hctiws rewop eht delcyc terref ehT
.cinap ot tuoba hguoht sa gnikahs dna
,tuoba smra sih gnivaw elihw selcric ni dnuora gnipmotS
.sbos otni nwod gnikaerb erofeb ,denihw eh
,llew sa mih no dloh a dah llits esruc ehT
,kcolria eht otni enihcam eht devohs neht nem owt ehT
,pu derewop saw ti taht gnitacidni llits saw yalpsid stI
,yad htfif eht nO   2 fo 2 traP
",ffo eriw eht lluP"
.stsif sih htiw setalp kced eht no gnidnuop ,enorp gniyal won saw flow eht erehw
.stiderc dnasuoht eno
ediced ot gniyrt ylisub saw reh fo tser eht elihw
---  .redlew detcennocsid eht ta
mih dniheb thgir erew feihC dna geR
.tekcaj reh fo tnorf eht nwod ti deppord dna
,lenap eht fo tnorf ni gnidnats saw flow ehT
.deddon feihC ehT
sraet fo lluf seye siH  .tsol dekool eh
.ecalp otni eriw eht dekcol flow eht dna
"?pu evig lliw eh kniht uoy oD"
.niatpac eht detuohs "?deneppah tahW"
,gnideeccus mih no teb dah nosrep eno tsael ta eciton did eh hguoht
lenap eht fo kcab eht ta seriw dessorc fo riap eht dna
,etam s’reenigne eht ,dorlE ,emit tsaL
.redlew eht htiw devirra feihC emit eht yb
yrots siht ni sretcarahc eht dnuora ecalp gnikat seirots eroM
,knird tnetop eht yb detarogivnI
.dluohs taht srotacidni gniknilbnu daed eht dna
.sruoh wef a tsuj ni niaga 'lamron'
ta dekool nem eerht llA  .neerg deniamer syaler eht fo llA
,loop gnitteb etacirtni na yb
.eil a saw ti wenk eh hguoht ,flesmih gnillet tpek eh
.noitartsurf sih ni enola t'nsaw eh taht wonk mih tel ot tsuj neve ro
dneps ot gniog saw ehs woh
,htap erutuf sti ni detsixe sllew ytivarg dna smetsys yratenalp tahw
",gniht eruS"  .flow eht deksa
.kcen reh ta namsilat revlis eht htiw gniyot yldi
nevig saw eh ksat elpmis eht dna
.neerg saw gnihtyreve deciton I nehw
",ecalp ni ti pmirc woN"
yob eht dehctaw eh sa
detaoc llits saw tsniaga desserp saw eh elop eht taht ees ot detnioppasid saw eh ,seye sih gninepO
,dessap won evah syad ruoF
.seye sih desolc dna
ylsuovren feihC eht ta dekool flow ehT
,sredluohs sih morf detfil neeb dah thgiew suomrone na hguoht sa
---  .yellag eht ot gnola flesmih deirruh neht ,dehsulb dorlE
,egdirb eht no feihC eht
.yrruFoS no dnuof eb nac
.ylgnirussaer kcab eht no mih dettap dna tsehc sih ot
..siht yb detaefed eb ot reenigne tsrif eht t'nera uoY"
,delaes saw rood eht tnemom ehT
',efas saw dorlE erus ekam
,tekcaj thgilf sih denethgiarts geR  .cidem eht deksa
elop eht tsniaga daeherof sih deppat ylthgil eH
.ezeeuqs a redluohs s'terref eht evag geR  ".rehtegot
.tfel s'feihC eht ot lenap eht no
,elzzum sih revo depmalc swap htob
eriw der ynit eht ot gnitniop ,dias eh
",uoy sa emaS  .peels t'ndluoC"
.detamina yrev emaceb ylneddus
.xobloot sih kcik dna kcab luah
gninrom yadretsey ecnis flesti gnillitsid neeb ylbaborp dah tI
,ti retfa ni selbac eht gnulf dorlE nehw
,ecaps otni tuo yltnelis dekcus saw redlew eht dna
puc nit a pu dekcip eh sa
"?enoyreve si erehW"
”esruC s’reenignE ehT“
werc eht morf reehc duol a saw erehT
,dedne egdirb eht no tfihs sih retfA
.elims a htiw dias eh ",did uoy seY  .seY"
,efil ot emac redlew cinotohp eht dna
aremac ytiruces eht no erugif ehT
noci eht depsalc ehs
.ti otni eeffoc revo-tfel eht fo tsal eht delbbird dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
dna deddon tibbar ehT
"?erocs eht s'tahw ,ecnaL"
thgil der gniknilb a yb deinapmocca
".tey sa sevlesmeht detaeper ton evah hcihw srorre suolamona euqinu etarapes neetruof neeb osla evah erehT"
",eno sihT"  .feihC eht
,dehtolc ylluf llits ,dorlE dna
?geR ,egdirb eht no uoy era yhW"
.niatpaC eht dias
,rovaf sih ni eb ot kool ton did sddo ehT
"?srood erusserp eht dereggirt eh sah semit ynam woH"
.pu dne thgim ti erehw dna
,sregnif reh neewteb gnivom latem looc eht tlef ehs sA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,niaga fles yppah lausu sih dednuos eH
,thgit erew srotcennoc eht fo lla ,deppirt ton dah ytefas ehT
degnirc feihC eht nehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.peels ot elbanu osla saw redneH
.desolc ti sa tsuj rood eht hguorht eno fo dne liat eht gnikcik
eert revlis ynit eht ot ti dehcuot dna ,regnif sih dessik feihC
,sregnif nwo reh gnissiK
,detisiv yltnecer dah werc eht secalp citoxe fo serutcip ro
,metsys feileb nwo reh ni dah ehs htiaf hcum woh gninoitseuq saw reh fo trap ynit a
,ecnaL detuohs "!yaw ekaM  !htap a raelC"
"?ti si emit tahW  ?tsafkaerB"
.ylmlac dna yltfos
,yltneloiv eldnah eht koohs terref ehT
.efas eb ot tsuj ,raey dna ,etad
.deeccus ro liaf dluow eh rehtehw no steb erew erehT
,tiderc eno rof ylno saw teb eht hguoht dna
,yletarucca erom ro
nepo deppans srood retuo ehT
,nokraD ahsarheT yb
.ytpme ti dnuof dna yellag eht otni derednaw dorlE
,redlew cinotohp eht fo ssam detamitse eht gnitaluclacer yldetaepeR
.ecnaraeppa neddus s’niatpac eht ta deltrats
.smelborp erom ni detluser ylno
rallip troppus a tsniaga denael eh
.eulb ot eulb dna
.kcar eht ot detnuom gnieb saw eludom tsal eht sa tsuj
,tpels yllautca reven ohw ,ecnaL
”esruC sreenignE ehT“
dnoces eht saw sihT
deriw llits erew yehT
,niard eht nwod diuqil kcalb eht fo tser eht deruop eh
"?KO  .tser emos teg htob nac ew neht
oT'  .saremac ytiruces eht ot kcab mih gniward tpek ytisoiruc dibrom tub
seriw htiw seludom dna syaler ehT
.enod m'I  !feihC ,yeH"
.ti dniheb tuoba gnilialf dna gnihtirw selbac sti htiw
,tekcos rewop sti otni deggulp saw redlew eht erehw ot revo deklaw yllausac neht geR
.yellag eht ot kcolf ot nageb enoyreve dna
.kcohs ni nepo ediw seye sih dna
.feihC eht dettimda
,daehklub eht tsniaga depmuls htob
.eno ot dnasuoht-eno erew sddo eht
.detceje saw ti nehw gniraeb dna yticolev s’pihs eht htiw denibmoc
.flow detsuahxe eht deksa
,ffo tnew rezzub gninraw A
",gnihton llits ,epoN"
.nirg a htiw deksa eh
flow eht sa ylwols dehcaorppa htob geR dna feihC ehT
.thgil der gniknilb eht ta gnitniop ,niaga tibbar eht deksa
.seriw eht gnitcennocer ylisub dorlE htiw
ssergorp rieht kcehc ot ni deppots geR
,feihC eht dias ",gnivael uoy tuoba gnihtyna dias ydoboN
.rehtegot kcab lla ti tup mih pleh lliw I nehT  .mih llet ll'I"
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
"?feihC uoy dluow ,redlew eht teseR  !timmaD"
"?ti htiw gnola esruc live fo dnik emos koot ti taht sepoh eht ni
,der tnew lenap eht ni syaler eht fo flah
.feihC eht deilper
.gnihgual nageb dna
.dnim sih ni lla ti ees llits dluoc eH
,eb dluohs yeht sa yllamron gnitarepo dna
.dnim sih fo kcab eht ni tnamrod deniamer dah taht
.IA eht deunitnoc
neerg erew syaler eht fo llA
,ecnacifingis eht tuoba erusnu saw dorlE
.detaeper eh ",wonk I ,wonk I"
,t'ndluohs taht sthgil gniknilb eht
.llaw eht fo tuo droc eht dekrej dna
,ecalp ni ti dlew ot flow eht gnivaeL
,riap eht etalutargnoc ot denrut eh nehw
,swodahs gnisahc morf mih tneverp dna ecivda egas mih evig ot
redlew eht ot kcab deklaw eH
dorlE dna feihC eht
.gnitteb eht fo tcejbus eht erew
",tnuoc tsol ev'I  .wonk t'nod I ,hO"
mih evag taht elims ehT
.sseltser yllausunu flesmih dnuof sselehtreven
,feihC eht deksa "?tahW"
.riahc dnammoc eht otni kcab depmuls dna
.dah niatpac eht sa tsuj ,dessap eh sa
,hcum evom t'ndid tI
.egdirb eht otno deppets eh sa geR
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.flow eht ot dellac eh ",won yrT"
.divil saw eh taht suoivbo saw ti
.smra sih ni selbac fo eldnub gniliart eht deirrac eh sa
.lenap nepo eht ta
niaga tinu eht elcyc rewop ot tuoba saw eH
.knub sih ssorca delwarps
"!seriw dessorc fo riap a tsuj s’tI"
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
",sruoh xis rehtona rof deludehcs ton si tsafkaerB
.swen dab eht reviled ot yab ograc eht ot nwod tnew feihC
neht ,lenap eht ta kcab neht ,rehto hcae
.spil sih no egdums kcalb a gnivael
kcalb ot kcalb ,'ylreporp'
,dorlE yb ylesolc dewollof
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
regnif gnikahs a detniop dna
.feihC eht dias ",sruoh ruof rehtona rof trats t'nseod tfihs ruoY
.repsihw a ni feihC eht depsag "?od uoy did tahW"
.kcen reh dnuora erow ehs efiL fo eerT eht tsniaga ti dehcuot dna
.lenap nepo eht ta serutseg edur
.noitelpmoc ot reraen on si
,llams revewoh ,seitiliba sih ni htiaf dah enoemos taht egdelwonk eht dna
,dluoc eh fi pleh oT
,niaga neerg denrut gnihtyreve
,ksat elpmis ylgnimees a nevig saw
.yaler sti htiw tcatnoc gnikam ylerab ylno saw hcihw
,sretrauq nwo sih ni geR
,nokraD ahsarheT yb
"?ti t'nseod ,railimaf sdnuoS"
deksa "?gnipmirc uoy erew eriw hcihW   .ti ees I ,haeY"
.tsif sih htiw nottub 'egrup' eht dehsams geR
,noitcennoc tsal siht pmirc yllaunam ot tuoba saw I ,daed saw redlew eht ecniS  !gnihtoN"
,rotinom ytiruces eht drawot bmuht a dekooh geR
"!kced no niatpaC  !hguorht gnimoC"
,yab ograc eht ni ecalp gnikat
,semit elpuoc a roolf eht no ti degnab
,segassem 'dnuof dna tsol'
.deddon terref eht dna
.pu dnats kcen s'feihC eht no ruf eht edam hcihw
.flow eht dias ",llac fo trop txen eht ta em evael nac uoy dna
,kloy gnireets eht no pu teef sih htiw ,riahc dnammoc eht otni depparts
deddon feihC ehT
ffo eriw der eht lluP"
ksat tnerruc sih dna eh taht ezilaer ot stnemom wef a mih koot tI
.eciov s'ecnaL deilper
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
eussi eht xif ot tpmetta hcae sa ,lortnoc fo tuo delarips yldipar hcihw
saw feihC ,egdirb eht nO
,ecnetsixe sti fo mih dednimer ylno dah ti reuqnoc ot tpmetta tsetal siht dna
,niatpac eht detaeper ",yaler eht fo
regnif sih fo pit eht dessik neht
.pu gnivig erofeb tsal dluow eh syad ynam woh no steB
,daeh sih ni sdrow eht raeh dluoc feihC eht ,detum oidua eht htiw nevE
flesmih ot gnilims saw geR
.tey kcab degnahc neeb ton dah
eb dluow gnihtyreve taht niatpac eht demrofni feihC eht
,edis eht nwod detsil semoctuo htiw
meht neewteb gnidnats tub
.skraps on erew ereht tub ,setalp kced eht ssorca eborp eht deggard neht
.ecived eht dekcehc eh sa feihC deilper
.elbaliava saw rewop taht gnitacidni yalpsid eht etipsed ,gnihton llits saw erehT
,namsilat ynit eht hcuot ot denrut eh nehW
.dehgis niatpac ehT
,ti dnuof I yaw eht kcab siht fo lla tup ot gniog m'I  .tiuq I  .erom oN
delbasid ytefas eht dna detresni yek sih dah ydaerla geR
.dirg eht gnitalupop stnuoma dna sddo gnitteb eht dna
,gnola redlew eht dehsup yeht sa
---  .ksat sih ot denruter dna
”esruC s’reenignE ehT“   yojne esaelP
,nokraD ahsarheT yb
"!seriw eht ..tub ..tuB
,emit tnerruc eht fo mih demrofni ecnaL
,deb reh no ekawa yal ehS
.gnalc yvaeh a htiw revo gnillaf erofeb edis eno ot derettiks ti erehw
,desolc srood retuo eht nehW
,meht neewteb gnissorc-ssirc
.rodirroc eht ni derehtag dah ohw srebmem werc suoiruc eht ot detuohs eh "!em no si reeB"
seitivitca eht fo ffo dnim sih ekat dluow taht gnihtyna dnif ot gniyrt yletarepsed
.tsohg a ekil rodirroc eht nwod detaolf margoloh sih sa
dnah sih desiar ylsuoituac
.yob roop eht htiw ereht nwod eb ot detnaw eH
ekam dna lialf ot deunitnoc flow eht sa
.regnif gnikahs a gnitniop llits ,dekaeuqs eh
.nwo sti fo nerdlihc evah ot hguone dlo won si moor tahc CRI s’ohw
.nosinu ni feihC dna dorlE dekeirhs "?tahW"  .geR dias
,lenap eht fo noitcerid lareneg eht ni dnah sih devaw eH  "..siht
.etunim a tsuj tiaW"