,reh sekat ti  ,erif eht
,tfiws nur sexof ehT lwoh sevlow eht
dniw a sesir erehT
eraweb retteb dah srelworp eht ,srelwoh ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,naD yb
!ria nmutua dloc eht hguorht spael eh yldloB
erad a si reyarp s’yerp dna
!erah eht si kciuQ
ria dloc ni doog sllems erah ytsat mraW
—raeb eht slworg yrgnuh
etihw deracs a fo
niaga esir t'now srehto eht fo emos tuB
,”eraH ehT“   :yojne esaelP
eralf slirtson s’erah ehT
erif eht otni spael erah eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
niar eht si os dna
muigleB fo ,erah eht
,ereht stis erah ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.naD yb meop a uoy gnidaer m’I yadoT dna
gnirad dna egaruoc ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
)raews serah woh si hcihw(
;tnelis si erah ehT lworp sevlow eht
riapsed dna epoh si ecnetsixe s’erah A
suoiciled gnillems fO
”eraH ehT“ saw sihT      …erah
reyarp a rettu dluow eh ,yarp dluoc erah eht fI …erehwesle
rrRRrrrRRRrroN ot noitacided ni naD yb meop a
niap eht snword ti
,ereh ton ,rial a sah erah ehT
,nroh a seralb erehT
eri ni yrc sevlow eht dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
?ereht teg eh lliw tuB
,reh sevol ti ,erif eht
erif fo sllaw ,daeha dna ,yerp rieht ees yehT
erah eht rof tpecxE
.ereht mih ekat sedirts gnipael s’erah eht dnA
ereht si eno on dna ,gniniar si ti
reve sa luferac sa
,erif eht otni snur ehs ,erah eht
erah eht snur deusrup sa
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
denrub ton si ehs
,dneirf a si niar ehT
won dnA  eerf si ehs
,yerp si erah eht tuB erah eht dluow raews neht ,raews dluoc erah eht fI
ereht si erah ehT  ria nmutua dloc eht ni