,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,tacs fo ecart a rO
:dlot lla ,ykcul os ton m'I
— gnitacixotni ,ydaeH
,dessap gnol ,etoyoc eht rO
.yrteop sdaer enoyreve ton tuB
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot
;emit dnA — htaed dna efiL
”em erussa sgod ehT“ saw sihT
,doolf eht retfa tfel hsif gnittor a fo tnecs eht nI
.reh fo tseb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM yrteoP ot gninetsil er’uoY
,”em erussa sgod ehT“   yojne esaelP
— erutuf ,tneserp ,tsaP
.teop eht yb daer
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
— gninaem fo semulov era erehT :em erussa sgod ehT
,seirots dnif nac uoy erehw
.enilno eerf rof daer ro esahcrup ot skoob dna ,smeop
.teop eht yb daeR
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,uargnegiE noitcelloc reh morf si meop s’yadoT
yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb meop a
,kni.oykam ta elbaliava si gnitirw reH
.elbat eht no sdnah ruoy tser uoy yaw eht dnA sdrow morf ylno sesiR
— gninaem fo tnecs hcir ehT
.2 .lov stsaeB deziliviC ni dehsilbup ylsuoiverp saw dna