.taR eht kcab derepsihw
.tnemesuma hsiyob ylliS"
".trac eht tuoba enod eb ot si ereht tahw ees dna og s'teL .mih dnim reveN
,evots-gnikooc a—
.emitefil a rof noitapucco eniuneg ylno eht
.daeha skeew lareves rof
.noonretfa nedlog a saw tI
.yldeggod ,taR eht dias ",erac t'nod I"
,mih deef ot repeekesuoh sih detcurtsni dna
.noitidepxe ytsud siht ni boj tseitsud eht rof
;gnillirht os dna
.revo ti klat ll'ew dna"
,esroh eht teiuq ot gniyrt ysub saw eloM ehT  "!poop-
gnilbbad-a nwod
.taob eht evael ll'ew erehw
.dias eh "?swen eht
,ydaer etiuq erew yeht nehW
.stnetnoc sti dna trac eht tuoba dluoc yeht snoitcerid tahw evag dna
.esuoh-taob egral a fo wodahs eht otni dessap yeht sa sllucs sih deppils eloM eht dna
,esuoh-taob sih ot sdael
,ygrene fo ertnec krad a htiw ,tsud
",yad-dooG" meht evag
.emoh ta teprac-ruolrap sih doolf ot desu
;trac eht ni sknub elttil rieht ot ni denrut yeht tsal tA
!snwod gnillor eht ,sworegdeh eht
.srieht dnim ot meht evael dna
,redral ruo peek ew ereH
,emoh revir eht nwod dellucs
,uoy erofeb dlrow elohw ehT
.ssenitraeh taerg htiw
.gninrom siht niart ylrae na yb nwoT ot pu tnew daoT
,strap eseht ni sesuoh tsecin eht fo eno yllaer si siht dna
,mih tuoba hcum os draeh ev'I
"!era uoy erehT"  .sleehw der dna
.thgis yrros a deedni saw tI
,snoitapicitna dna semehcs ni peed ydaerla erew ohw
!tesno tnecifingam ym fo ekaw eht ni
.tuo deyalp si gnitaoB"
.stnemtif elttil sti lla dna
,daor eht ni nwod dna pu decnad taR ehT
,taob dna ,eloh a ni evil dna ,revir dlo ym ot kcits ot gniog ma I dnA
noisiv ylnevaeh taht ,lufituaeb
,saw uoy ksa ot detnaw I tahw tuB"
.rehtegot ffo tes yeht sa
,stsif htob gnikahs ,detuohs eh "!snialliv uoY"
strac elttil dirroH
.mih koot ruomuh eht sa ,tfahs eht no gnittis ro
;gnitpmet os saw ti fo tcepsa hserf siht dna
eb ot ekil eW !sekil eh tahw rof enoyrevE
goD fo ecioV ehT fo edosipe tsrif eht ot gninetsil er’uoY
,drow a derewsna reven daoT ehT
,uoy tuohtiw eganam ylbissop t'nac I
yrgna dna gnirettulps
.eloM eht degdun taR eht
,ot sgnoleb ti ohw dna rac-
.ti tsniaga tnialpmoc a egdol dna
smaeb ssorc eht morf gnuls
.gnol yrev ekat t'now tI
depmuj seitic dna snwot
trac eht fo edis eht yb gnigdurt rehtie lamina hcae
,sgabeson gnuh dna
dednem dna dehctef eb ot trac eht rof egnarra dna s'thgirwleehw
.seitilaivirt ni derednauqs
,gnineve eht ni etaL
"!didnelps si siht"
;meht fo hcae fo woble eht edisni wap a tsurht dna
,raey wen eht etarbelec oT dna
!nameltneg a rof efil laer eht si sihT
"!struoC eht lla hguorht uoy ekat ll'I !uoy troper ll'I
,taR ,uoy ot kcits syawla ll'I"
.dlo fo morf mih wonk I ,ees uoY
,yawa tnew taR eht oS
,yad lla ysae yrev sgniht nekat dna etal nesir dah ohw
;daor-hgih tsrif rieht
.erutan didnac a dah eh dna
.seenk sih no tuo daerps pam egral a dna
.ecnelis lufniap s'tnemom a saw erehT
,hctid eht ni edis sti no yal
.saw eh erehw gniniamer
.daoT no llac ot emit gnorw eht reven s'tI
,taR derutan-doog eht dias ",ylniatrec ,yhW"
.ylnrets dednamed eh
.emoh ta gnipeekesuoh fo seugitaf dna seirrow dna serac eht retfa
,slavretni ta gniyas saw taR dna ,gniklat saw daoT tsael ta—
,gnignulp ,gniraeR
.noissap htiw detropsnart ylpmis
sknub gnipeels elttiL
.yad eht rof dnim sih morf yrteop gnissimsid dna
mih fo edis eht yb rehtona koot eloM eht elihw
.tnemtnetnoc dna yoj taerg s'taR eht ot
!eerf gnilbbaD ,pu sliat ,nwod sdaeH
.enod eb ot gnihton yllaer si ereht esuaceB"
,gnola deddolp eh sa ,gnimaerd
.klat rieht ot netsil dna
,ylrettu meht depparwne dna dednilb taht tsud fo duolc gnipolevne na gnulf
"!tnatropmi tsom s'tI
ereht yccab—ereh retaw-adoS
,keerc eht pu dedilg yehT
,dnoces a fo noitcarf eht rof ria dna htrae lla dessessop
,ti htiw pu nekat yrev saw eh os ,flesmih ti desopmoc tsuj dah eH
rehtona gnisoppuS
,sreniram lavir fo
"!revir dlo ruoy tuoba klaT
,derepmet-doog syawlA
",yttaR dlo doog raed uoy ,woN"
,ereh mih evael t'nac eW"
".ydaoT sah ,seitilauq taerg emos tog sah eh tuB
,ecno ta ereh pu dehctef eb ot erew uoy taht sredro tcirts htiw
,retteb wonk ot thguo ohw ,swollef uoy ees ot yrros thgirnwod em sekam tI
!pirt siht no emoc ot gnitnesnoc
,daeh eht yb mih koot dna
.efas ton s'tI
,emas eht llA .eb ot tog sah—
;ylegavas taR eht dias ",daoT rehtob ,O"  "?gnola emoc ot erew gnihT
:daeh s'daoT ssorca mih gnisserdda ,eloM eht ot dias eh
,ylgnirolpmi ,daoT dias
;sesuineg eb lla t'nac ew—
,niaga spets eht dednecsed yeht sa ,deunitnoc eh
detrons ylno taR ehT
,esruoc fo ,tnellecxe
neeb evah thgim ti fi sa sdnuos ti
,daor-hgih eht no tuo emac yeht taht
"?'noonretfa siht' dna ',trats' dna
.eeb tnatsid a fo enord eht ekil ,muh gninraw
,gnihsif knab eht no gnittis saw
".kcohs rieht derevocer evah sevren ruoy llit dna
,od I sa od dna em ot kcits ot gniog s'eloM ,erom s'tahw dnA
.ycnacav otni gnirats dna
;gniht delttes a saw pirt eht taht meht fo eerht lla yb detnarg rof nekat demees noos ti ,wohemoS
!tmaerd neve reven ,wenk reven I
.krow fo erahs riaf sih od dluohs daoT taht erac koot stseug owt eht emit siht ylno
,”swolliW eht ni dniW ehT“   :yojne esaelP
,mih ot gniht a wen os saw suorutnevdA efiL ehT !eloM rooP
,hctid tseraen eht rof pmuj meht edam taht dnuos fo lrihw a dna
,snihc dah skcud fi eb dluow snihc rieht erehw rednu tsuj
".efil ni ottom ym s'tahT '!srehto rof
.trac eht fo edis eht yb ssarg eht no gnittis reppus elpmis rieht eta dna
,detsuahxe ylhguoroht ,gnitser erew slamina owt eht dna
.taR retaW eht fo eloM eht deksa
worrub eht fo tuo emac elom detartsurf a nehw
,tfel eht no keerc taht dna" ;taR eht dias
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom ynam dnif nac uoY
,eloM eht devresbo
,taR eht gnidragersiD
!tnemeticxe ,tseretni ,egnahc ,levarT
,tuo taob eht teG"
,seirassecen htiw rethgit llits srekcol eht dekcap daoT emitnaeM
.taR tneitap eht deilper
,staob emosdnah ynam was yeht ereH
.mih egilbo ot gnihtyna tsomla od dluow dna
,daoT fo hcraes ni snwal dekced-rewolf yag eht ssorca dellorts dna
"!ym O !ym O !poop-poop O !ssilb O
"swolliW eht ni dniW ehT"
thgis tsrif ta evol ni nellaf dah eh dna
,sevlehskoob ,srekcol
noitapucco etarapes s'yad hcae tuo gninnalp
,ohw ,esroh yerg dlo eht erutpac ot meht tes dna
evisnepxe yrev dna egral a
.enotonom ymaerd a ni
"!won tsuj pu gninrut ruoy ,si ti ykcul woh wonk t'nod uoY !gnihtemos evah dna edisni emoC
gniyekcoj sselkcer eht yb laohs a no nevird
"!mih htiw enod ev'I"
!dlrow eht uoy wohs ot tnaw I ?taob dna
,ecnayonna emertxe nwo sih ot dna
"?si ti tahw ees⁠ uoY"
,knab revir eht no gnittis saw taR ehT
a ro s'htimskcalb a ot og ot evah ll'uoy neht dnA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.detcepsus taR eht neve naht reraen deedni saw dne ehT  "!thgin dooG
",ma I esruoc fO"  "?eloM ,uoy t'nera
eM' .ylimaerd daoT derumrum
",revir elohw eht no esuoh tseniF"
meht no tuo gnarps ,neeserofnu dna teelf
'.noonretfa siht trats ruo ekam ew nehw ,nettogrof neeb sah revetahw gnihton taht dnif ll'uoy"
"!daoT ,ssa na gnieb pots O"
daoT yb ffo dlot neeb dah
,0202 ,ht5 tsuguA no
.daoT fo reerac retfa eht no
ereH  .gnidda pleh ton dluoc eh
emaharG htenneK yb ,II retpahC
.navarac eht fo roiretni eht otni dna spets eht pu ylregae mih dewollof dna
,dehsams swodniw dna slenaP
.ylmrif taR eht deilper ",lla ta gnihtoN"
,ecnart a fo tros a ni mih dnuof yehT
nni na ot og lliw I dna eloM eht ,elihwnaeM
,emoh morf selim dna yppah dna derit
.egats tsrif sti ni ,yaw taht mih sekat syawla ti dna
rof uoy ot ma I degilbo woh
,mih erofeb tuo dehcterts sgel sih
.skcud eht sdneirf sih htiw ynapmoc ni
;trac lufituaeb rieht tuoba sgniht ecin yas ot deppots ro
.yllufreehc taR eht deilper
,yllacitehtap dedda eh
.nrets eht ni ylbatrofmoc flesmih delttes taR eht elihw
,lamina elbulov a yllarutaN
draeH" .mih dnif ot gnola gnillorts emac
".YTTID 'SKCUD"   dellac eh hcihw
.trac eht thgir ot tneiciffus ton erew stroffe detinu rieht tub
!oot ,erutnevda fo
,deticxe dna detseretni ylsuodnemert saw eloM ehT
.dias eh ",yttaR ,thgir llA"
,enecs eht no deraeppa daoT emit eht yb
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,gninrom worromot yawa nur ew llahS" .derepsihw eh
.enod syawla ev'I sa
,mih morf yawa deppils etiuq dah ssenkcis-emoh siH
,maerd yppah a ni gniklaw lamina na ekil
.wonk uoy ,yaw ym ylno s'tI"
.gnos elttil a gnignis
,ti od mih was daoT eht yletanutrofnU
",t'nsi ti ,t'nsi ti ,neht lleW"
,em dniheb eil taht sraey detsaw esoht llA"
,egalliv tseraen eht ot ffo degdurt eloM eht
ekil yeht nehw ekil yeht tahw od ot dewolla eb swollef t'nac yhW' ,yas yehT"
,sgel sih tuo gnikcik ,daoT dna
pu meht thguac daoT dna
.emit a retfa gniod ni dedeeccus eh hcihw
,reviuq-a teef wolleY ,sliat 'sekard ,sliat 'skcuD  !lla sliat pU
.elbisnes eb s'teL .ereh kool ,woN
".ecnatniauqca sih ekam ot tnaw os od I dna
dna sknab no gnittis swollef rehto
.yteirav dna ezis yreve fo selttek dna sguj
'!strac deruoloc-yranac—strac nommoc—
,tliub reve saw taht tros sti fo trac tsenif yrev eht si siht !dnim dnA
,nus eht ni knab revir eht no tas dna
,gninrom remmus thgirb eno ,ylneddus eloM eht dias ",YTTAR"
nwot eht gnihcaer nO
.tsugsid taerg ni ,daoT eht detpurretni "!gnitaob !hoop
saw syawla llaH daoT ta gnihtyreve sa
,kcoddap eht derreferp ylknarf eH
"?revir eht no eloh dlo raed ruo ot kcab og dna—
dlrow wen lufrednow dna reeuq a otni democlew flesmih dnif ot
"poop-pooP" ehT !meht no saw tI
.detnaw I slamina yrev eht era uoY
,rood sih ot daoT gniklaw-peels
,teknalb sih rednu morf tuo dehcaer eloM ehT
,taht meht dewohs noitcepsni luferac A
.snoitome larutan sih ot flesmih denodnaba ylpmis siht sa hcus noitautis war wen a ni
;tsael eht ni mih deredisnoc ydobon dna
ot yas ot desu eh sgniht gnitib dna enif eht lla tcellocer ot gniyrt saw eh dna
.rennam sselmia taht ni seigrene ruoy lla gnidneps
.meht dnuor gnicnad
,eloM eht gnineve gniwollof ehT
,nepo eht otni esuoh-hcaoc eht fo tuo nward ,ereht dna
.ylsuoretsiob daoT deirc
,dekrabmesid yehT
,yaw fo tros yffins dna ffits taht ni gniklat nigeb t'nod"
;retaw eht ni enon tub ,pils a no pu deluah ro
!tlobrednuht taht ,maebnus taht ,naws taht—
.ylgniriapsed eloM eht deirc
,emaharG htenneK yb
,gnilbbad-a era skcuD
.redluohs eht yb mih koohs taR ehT  "!poop-pooP"
.erac yllaer t'nod I ,esruoc fO
,snoitatibah morf raf nommoc etomer a no pu werd yeht
senidras ,retsbol dettop
,gninrom txen gnitrats rof emac emit eht nehw ,ecneuqesnoc nI
tniaf a draeh yeht
yldab uoy tnaw I
,snap ,stop dna
noonretfa eht llit ton saw ti dna
,warts a dewehc eh sa ,ylwols taR eht dias
fo duolc llams a was yeht ,kcab gnicnalG
".hguone noos etiuq ti tuoba lla raeh llahs eW
,trohs dehtaerb eH
.flesruoy ti ekil rehtar uoy wonk uoY
!worrom-ot keew txen ni—yad-ot ereH
eugra t'nod dna ,delttes ti redisnoc esaelp os
".ruovaf a uoy ksa ot tnaw I ,esaelp uoy fi"
ylneddus gniraeppa ,noom wolley a dna
.talf s'taht dna ,gnimoc ton m'I"
"!daoT ,ereh kool ,woN"
.niaga ,ti fo raeh ot ro ,trac eht ees ot tnaw reven I
uoy—uoy ,nemyawhgih uoy ,slerdnuocs uoY"
.sesoprup lacitcarp lla rof sselesu etiuq
.ecno ta ereht pu elddap ll'ew dna
,efil evitimirp eht fo yticilpmis eht tuoba suorutpar os snaem on yb saw daoT
"?daoT tuoba tahw tuB"
.ecrof yb deluah saw eh ecnehw
,daor eht edis rehtie no sdrahcro kciht fo tuo
,flesmih yb daor eht fo elddim eht ni gnittis
— trofmoc dna evol fo
trohs gnihtaerb llits
,dias dna ,swap-erof rieht pu dleh
,noitanigami sih yb deretsam syawla dna
,stiucsib—ees uoY"
,knub sih ni ecalp sih emuser ot detpmetta deedni dna
.od reven sdaf siH
.stnemegnarra eht ta kool dna edisni emoC
sruoloc gniwolg hcus ni edisdaor eht dna efil nepo eht fo syoj eht dna
nwo rieht ni reppus ot nwod tas
,gniht laer eht derevocsid ev'I ,oN
.emoc ot tog ev'uoy wonk uoy esuaceb
"!uoy t'nac ,dnah a raeb dna emoC"
,yllacitamolpid ,dias eh
taht fo nialpmoc
,dlrow ediw eht revo derettacs snit-enidras ,ffo leehw eno
.flesmih gnidnapxe dna gnilddarts ,daoT eht deirc
",esoppus I ,gniwor ruoy tuoba s'tI"
.hctid eht ni edis sti no
",revir ym tuoba klat t'nod I"
,meht gnissap ,srerafyaw derutan-doog
,goD fO ecioV ehT fo edosipe ht001 eht no deraeppa retpahc tsrif ehT
,skcen rieht elkcit dna
"!ym O !ym O !ym O"
.eloM eht ot ylmirg dias eh "!no emoC"
?ekat uoy lliw tahw woN .uoy fo htob—
eviL' .swollef uoy ot erusaelp evig ot tnaw ylno I
,ssenkrad eht ni wap s'taR eht rof tlef
!htrofecneh ,em erofeb daerps seil kcart yrewolf a tahw O !esilaer ylluf I taht won
,O"  "——yam uoy ,gnihcaoc fo ytitnauq yna dna ,ecneitap fo laed taerg a htiW
,ti fo tuo tfel yllufthgirf gnieb saw eh taht denialpmoc dah esroh eht ecnis ,mih ot gniklat
—miws hcaor eht erehW
,revewoh ,yaw rieht no raf yrev dedeecorp ton dah yehT
,ylisae daor-hgih eht gnola gnillorts erew yehT
meht dniheb raf nehw
,ruolrap edisrevir ysoc
,uoy rof efil laer s'erehT"
esnet tolip sti htiw ,etanoissap
,erif a til dna ,esroh eht ot was taR eht elihw dna
.dnah rehto eht ni tnapucco laciretsyh sti dna egac-drib eht gniyrrac
!ni s'eh etats detcartsid eht ni
snwal tpek-llew htiw
,noisserpxe deifsitas dicalp a erow ecaf sih
.riapsed ni mih morf denrut taR ehT  "!sdneirf fo tseb ym
,srae rieht ni tuohs nezarb a htiw gnar
,ylneddus sdaeh rieht no doots skcud eht nehw dnA
,gnipissog dna sdneirf sih pu gnikool neeb dah ohw ,taR eht nehw
,yldnuos yrev tpels daoT eht
,leehw sih gnigguh dna
kcab sih revo snier s'esroh eht dettonk taR ehT
!revir eht ni ysuB thgis fo tuo lla sllib wolleY
,tsafkaerb rof ydaer sgniht tog dna ,srettalp dna spuc s'thgin tsal denaelc dna
,ffo tes yeht dna
,llaH daoT morf raf yrev ton noitats a ta meht dednal gnivah niart wols a ,yllautnevE
.knab revir eht gnola lla ,tuoba deklat gnieb esle gnihton s'erehT"
.hsams sselepoh a etiuq ton s'ti tub ,emit ekat ll'tI
teef sih ot gnipmuj
;ti ni drib a htiw egac-drib a
',dewolla gnidnal oN
,senal-yb worran gnola dna snwod yssarg revo yad taht elbmar tnasaelp a dah yehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ecaf fo noisserpxe deipucco-erp a htiw
.daor eht fo edis eht ta hctid peed eht sdrawot sdrawkcab trac eht evord eh
",rettam taht rof ,esle erehwyna rO"
.rekcol a nepo gnillup
,etats sselepoh a ni erew selxa ehT
,erofeb sa ,yal yaw riehT
lessev deruoloc-yranac eht fo reppiks eht saw eh tnemom eht rof dna
,retsasid ereht dna
.sselepoh etiuq s'eH"
,ecaf sih no elims yppah a
.0202 ni ediserif eht ta ynapmoc em gnipeek rof uoy knahT
,llat sehsur eht hguorhT ,retawkcab eht gnola llA
.wollef emas eht syawla s'eh etal ro ylraE
.ylsuoituac eloM eht devresbo
,tnereffid yrev gnihtemos fo emit eht lla gnikniht dna—
".daoT ot hcum sa timda reven ew hguoht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .1202 ni
",lamina ecin yrev a eb tsum eH"
,mih pleh ot emac taR ehT
.ti htiw enod dna ,ti fo derit s'eH
"!tnialpmoC !noitats-eciloP"
",tuo ti ees ll'ew ,on ,oN"
,ylgnidrocca dray-elbats eht ot yaw eht del eH
,elbats nni na ta esroh eht tfel neht yehT
.dnats t'nac I gniht eno eht s'ti—
tnatsni na derevaw tI
,ezarg ot esool esroh eht denrut
.niap ni lamina ysaenu na ekil deliaw "!poop-pooP" tniaf a
,deeps elbidercni ta meht no gnicnavda
.thgir eht ot ereht revo era selbats ehT
"!thgis gnirrits ,suoirolG"
"!did I ,flesym lla me' dennalP
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
pooP" derumrum yltniaf eh slavretni ta dna
dna ssalg-etalp gnirettilg
tsud eht tuo morf elihw
.gninrom txen deb fo tuo mih esuor dluoc gnikahs fo tnuoma on dna
,dray-elbats eht sa raf sa tsuj
,enod neeb lla dah krow drah ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.mih dnuora dekool taR ehT
?daoT .rM no llac ot em ekat uoy t'now
kcoddap eht ot snoinapmoc sih del daoT tnahpmuirt won eht
?won pu nekat sah eh daf wen tahw rednow I
"!og uoy nehw yrros syawla
tceffe sti ni gnimlehwrevo ylpmis tub
",rehtien skcud eht t'nod roN"
!em defashcuov neeb sah taht
"!yob ym ,uoy fo lamina na ekam ot gniog m'I
,sdneirf owt sih tnioppasid ot raeb ton dluoc eH
htworgrednu neerg yhsulS
.ylluftsiw ,dedda eh
.trac elttil taht ni deidobme
,yttaR ,uoy rof revir eht nwod taob a dnes ot gniog tsuj saw I"
.ezeeuqs a ti evag dna
,wonk I taht won tub—won tuB
,detlusnoc neeb gnivah tuohtiw
.thgin-ot knabrevir ot kcab su teg ll'taht ereht niart a pu kcip yam ew kcul htiw dna ,noitats yawliar eht ot og ll'ew nwot eht ot teg ew nehw—pu ti evig I
hsarc gnidner-traeh a saw ereht neht—
.egde s'retaw eht ot nwod gnihcaer
,emoc ot syad eht ni od ot gniog saw eh lla tuoba gib deklat daoT
,knab a ni eloh a ni evil tsuj dna
,daor ytsud eht fo elddim eht ni nwod thgiarts tas daoT
eb ot si yas uoy tahw dna
rumrum ot draeh llits saw eh slavretni tA
"!ees llahs uoy tahw ees llahs uoy dna
,eloM eht fo dnof saw eh dna
,won syad rof taht ekil eunitnoc ll'eH
"?mih htiw od ot ew era tahW"
ruoh etal yrev a ta dna
!noitom fo yrteop ehT"
.yllayol ,eloM eht dias
",llaH daoT s'erehT"
".yas skcud eht tahw s'tahT
.llits tib doog a hsalps uoy hguoht
,riahc-nedrag rekciw a ni gnitser nopu deneppah yltneserp yeht mohw
,ylmraw meht fo htob fo swap eht koohs eH
.sthgir ot tup dna
noitats eht ot thgiarts tnew yeht
ruoy ot kcits ot naem t'nod ylerus uoY
,meht dnuora lla regral dna relluf werg srats elihw
revelc yrev ton s'eh spahreP
kniht t'nac uoY !yttaR ,O
,deppiks segalliV
,kcirb der dewollem fo esuoh dlo deifingid
,efil ruoy lla revir dlo ytsuf llud
,revir eht ni dneb a gnidnuoR
,wonk uoy ,hcir rehtar si daoT
,yltnahpmuirt daoT eht dias "!etelpmoc llA"
sriaffa nwo sih ot dnetta dna yawa og ot mih derolpmi yeht tsal tA
.8091 ni dehsilbup tsrif
.ti klaw ot evah tsuj llahs ew dna
,dah daoT eht seirassecen suoirav dna sgge dna klim rof ,ffo yaw gnol a
!levart ot yaw laer ehT
na dah ecalp eht dna
!levart ot yaw ylno ehT
,daeh s'esroh eht yb eloM eht
.em pleh ot tog ev'uoY
,degnahc saw enecs lufecaep eht
.prah a no sa eloM decneirepxeni eht nopu yalp ot dedeecorp eh
,ezarc wen a tog sah eH
"?mih ot yas uoy did tahw dna ;ylesicerp ,seY"
llaw eht tsniaga pu dedlof taht elbat elttil a—
".retteb eht trats a ekam ew renoos ehT
;noisserpxe luftsurtsim tsom a htiw gniwollof taR eht
,meht tuoba gnos a pu edam dna
rotom taht tuoba gnihtyna wonk yeht fi ees dna
.der yrev denrut dna
,sworegdeh eht ni srood tnorf rieht ta gnittis ,stibbar dna
.gnihgual tuo tsrub daoT nehT
,yawhgih ytsud eht ,daor nepo ehT
.mih htiw rettam eht saw tahw ees ot tnew yeht os
.ria detresed a dna desunu
,noitidepxe rieht ot
,ecno ta gniklat lla
'!si lla ti esnesnon tahW
saw hcihw—noehcnul gniruD
.daoT ,t'nod I wonk uoY"
,ydaer s'trac eht llit yats nac ew erehw smoor elbatrofmoc dnif dna
,em dniheb eil taht sraey detsaw eht terger ylno nac dna
.ria tneconni na htiw ,taR eht dias
,ecnatsid raf eht ni kceps a ot deldniwd neht dna
"!wonk uoy ,nuf rehtar ,llew—
.snoitcejbo lanosrep sih edir-revo ot erutan-doog sih dewolla
,gnihctans-htaerb ,esnemmi
,ylsuoixna eloM eht deksa
.si taht ,dlo yrev —won ta gnikool er'uoy llah-gniteuqnab eht s'tahT
.taR deilper ",slamina fo tseb eht deedni si eH"
.yrruh a ni gnihtyna ediced t'ndeen eW
!yaw sselkcer ym no deeps I sa em dniheb pu gnirps llahs sduolc-tsud tahW
.flesmih ot tfel eb ot mih rof efas eb t'ndluow tI
,ti edisni mih tup
.yltnangidni taR eht deirc "!t'nsi ti ,oN"
,knab eht raen oot evord yeht sa
.eloM eht ot noitcudortni na rof gnitiaw reven
.dedne si pirt siht llit daoT yb kcits ot thguo I tub ,yllufwa sknahT"
,yttaR raed ,em htiw emoC
,navarac yspig a was yeht
,daeh sih ta stroffe s'eloM eht lla fo etips ni ,ylidaets gnikcab
.ylesolc meht fo htob gnihctaw saw daoT
,mih ta srehtaef rieht gnikahs dna
?ti si ,esuoh dab yrev a hcus ton s'ti dnA
.retaw rednu si daeh ruoy nehw leef uoy lla etiuq yas ot elbissopmi si ti rof
!worrom-ot esle erehwemos ot ffo dna pu ,yad-ot ereH
fo daetsni ,ekil yeht sa dna
,tneb ylsselepoh selxa
.regnol on levart dluow trac eht
,ot denrut taR dna eloM eht oS
".ecnediser lufthgiled"
.si ti tahw s'taht ,emit fo etsaw reehS .oga gnol pu taht nevig ev'I
,moor-gnitiaw ssalc-dnoces eht ni daoT detisoped dna
"?daoT ,su pleh ot gnimoc uoy erA"
,retpahc dnoces siht ni ,dna
deredro sah eh dnA
",nodrap ruoy geb I"
tnemeticxe dna ria nepo hcum os retfA
,nwot tseraen eht ot selim xis ro evif s'tI"
.dessessop won si eH
,sgnileef retteb sih ta detcerid egaugnal ylevil s'eloM eht lla dna
era eW —llac dna lrihw stfiwS evoba eulb eht ni hgiH
pirt eht fo stcepsorp eht detniap eh
.mid dna lluf dna looC
deedni suotnemom retsasid—
;ti wenk ohw erac t'ndid dna flesmih teop on saw eH
,dnim sih ni decnivnocnu llits hguoht ,taR eht dna
.kcerw elbameederri na
,dnuob-lleps eht detrocse yeht
.gnihctac fo laed a koot dna
dniw fo tsalb a htiw dna
",yttaR ,ekil uoy revetahw od ll'I"
,ssenwen htiw gninihs
,uoy tuohtiw enog evah t'ndluow I
,emaharG htenneK yb "swolliW eht ni dniW ehT" fo II retpahC
,won gnidael lla erew yeht saw ti efil ysae
,kcoddap teiuq sih fo
',ew' tuoba gnihtemos yas uoy raehrevo I did tub"
!uoy fo wal eht evah ll'I—!sgoh-daor—
,esroh yerg dlo ehT
daoT eht no tnew
,no tnew eh "!uoy fo dnik woH"
",hcnul emos evah dna ,ni gnola emoC"
,neerg htiw tuo dekcip wolley-yranac a detniap
,ralucitrap ni erehwon morf yltnelis dna
,riahc ysae na otni flesmih gniworht ,taR eht dias
s'daoT tuoba kramer livic emos edam dna
nwod evid dluow eh ,lliw skcud sa
,dnim sih ni gnissap saw tahw was taR ehT
.eloM ot ylevisulcxe skramer sih desserdda egdurt yraew taht fo tser eht gnirud dna ,detrons eH—
.gniod erew uoy revetahw
,meht dniheb teef fo gnirettap a saw ereht nehw
.etanoitceffa os dna ,derutan-doog os ,elpmis oS"
.seceip otni derettahs saw leehw gnissim eht dna
.tnemeticxe rof riahc sih ni tis yldrah dluoc eloM eht taht
fo roiretni na fo espmilg s'tnemom a dah yeht
.trac eht fo mottob eht morf steksab dna ,yah fo seldnub ,snoino fo sten
.mih no eye tcirts a peek ot ecnepowt retrop a gnivig
hctid eht otni ylsselerac gnilf llahs I strac tahW
trac deruoloc-yranac eht htiw
;gniyfsitas dna hcir saw pu dekcik yeht tsud eht fo llems ehT
,hsaw rieht nehw sehcnual-maets fo sretsam
,sevlesmeht yb ti gnithgir ni dedeeccus yeht fi neve
,ti ot enim fo redniamer eht etoved ot esoporp I
ynapmoc meht peek ot emac
,uoy ot lla ti ewo I
,esuoh-taob eht morf taob rieht tuo tog yeht nehT
,noitasrevnoc rieht emuser ot denrut yeht ,ti gnidrager yldraH
rehtegot gniklat trac eht dniheb gniklaw taR retaW eht dna daoT eht
,yllufnam dna ylteiuq
"!wenk reven I kniht ot dnA"
!noziroh s'esle ydobemos syawla—
.edivorp ot nettogrof ,esruoc fo
.ylgnihtoos eloM eht deilper
!seitic ,snwot ,segalliv ,spmaC
.etavirP' ,syas draob-eciton eht erehw
"!niaga lamina gnikovorp siht htiw gnirusaelp-a gniog em hctac uoy reve fi dnA
!swollef uoy ,thgin doog ,lleW" ,dias ylipeels
;daor eht ni taes sih morf degdub ro
!gnignahc syawla s'taht noziroh a dna
"!emit eht lla—ti tuoba kniht I" :enot rewol a ni
,yoj rieht dna edirp rieht ,trac deruoloc-yranac eht dna—
,nwot eht ot teg ew sa noos sa"
)demees ti sa( tnatsni na ni nehw
saw sihT       ".rac-rotom
,revir eht ni gnimmiws neeb dah eh gninrom ylrae ecniS
",taR ,gnos elttil taht fo hcum yrev os kniht I taht wonk t'nod I"  !lla sliat pU
"!ydaoT ,tib a teiuq tis s'teL"
,dessenrah dna thguac saw esroh eht tsal tA
,sllucs eht koot dna taob eht otni tog eh sa
,meht gniees no pu gnipmuj ,deirc eh "!yarooH"
,nommoc eht ,htaeh eht
,yrruh a ni niaga ecafrus eht ot emoc ot decrof erew yeht llit
.evom ot gnireffo reven ,daoT derumrum
,tnasaelp a tahw gnikramer ,yag dna hserf
;ylireehc meht ot deltsihw dna dellac sdrib
.tnaw ylbissop nac uoy gnihtyreve—
,elpoep gnitnioppasid detah eH .derevaw dna
,eloM eht dias ",si ti os ,si ti oS"
.detiecnoc dna luftsaob htob si eh taht eb yam ti dna
retpahc dnoces eht si yrots s’yadot
,emosdnah a fo thgis ni emac yeht
,senal worran yb yrtnuoc ssorca
.elbatrofmoc dna tcapmoc yrev deedni saw tI
?meht tuoba sgniht dna yrteop dna skramer gnikam dna emit eht lla meht gnihctaw
.eh dias ",dnatsrednu I"
yllufitip gnibbos egac-drib eht ni drib eht dna
:ylprahs taR eht dias
.noitpecxe yna tuohtiw
",ti tuoba kniht I tuB
.reve rof strac htiw enod ev'I !trac eht dneM
!llems gnihctiweb taht tlems ro ,dnuos gnicnartne taht draeh evah reven thgim I
ylrae yrev—ylrae etiuq
.og flesmih tel ylpmis daoT eht—
",dnif ll'uoy—seonimod dna sdrac ,maj ,nocab ,repap-rettel—
,uoy ees ot dalg syawla
,stekcop sih otni peed sdnah sih tsurht dna
.reyortsed rieht fo ekaw ytsud eht no dexif llits seye sih
,nommoc a no ,erofeb sa ,depmac dna
.erom ecno eeb gninord a otni kcab degnahc
,noitats-ecilop eht ot thgiarts og ot evah ll'uoy
taht nees evah reven thgim I neht dna
,trac eht ta kool ot tnew eh nehT
.tuo tel eb ot gnillac dna
.pu mih kool s'tel dna gnola emoC
.rac-rotom gniraeppasid eht fo noitcerid eht ni yldexif derats dna
,doog yrev os eb lliw eh fi ,osla dneirf elbaima ruoy dna
,llew ylriaf no gnitteg er'uoY"
.deb ot mih tup dna ,mih sserdnu
.deirc yeht "!daoT !iH"
.esle gnihtyna ro eloM ot noitnetta reporp yap ton dluow dna
,rac-rotom tnecifingam eht dna ,occorom hcir