.stnemom feirb wef a rof niap eht dezitehtseana tI .muidats eht gnilcric devoleb sih
.mih sdrawot yllacitonpyh gnicnad sgel 42 htiw
,sthguoht suoirotciv htiw hsawA
.erised rieht fo ecnecsan eht ni trapa meht gniraet
.srehtaferof sih fo doolb eht saw der fo aes eht taht dna elohw mih deruoved dah flesmih naiN fi sa tlef eH .luos sih yrub dna mih no nwod emoc ot denetaerht hcihw sretsnom nedoow eguh emaceb secifide gnisopmi eht sa kcab gnireel stsaeb fo secaf eht was eh ,dworc eht ta ecnalg a gnilaetS
.emaf fo noitinifed yrev eht s'taht yleruS ?sdik fo elpuoc a dna stnemesrodne wef a fo ecirp eht s'tahw ,lla retfA
.margorp noitairtaper nogard rieht fo trap sa
.teknalb trofmocsid a ekil mih depolevne hcihw ,raef ot del siht dna noitatneirosid ot del ssendas siH
nogard gnicar tsetaerg eht
- sesroh rof dengised neeb dah tI
ytirohtua rieht tressa
.ssenitpme tsuj saw ereht woN
.mih rof t'nsaw ti tub ,thguoht eh ,suoitiporp eb yam thgie rebmun ehT
yojne esaelP  .yrruFoS no
.dab lla ton s'noissimbus
,esion fo bubbuh a saw ytic ehT
.ksat eht hsinif ot
luos sih fo erutrot eht hguorht gniog mih tpek dah ecnesba reh fo erutrot ehT
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.daeha raey eht rof ytirepsorp fo ngis a dna
,deraperp selkcahs sih htiw rotpac sih deips eH
.rebmuls gniytip-fles sih fo tuo néhC gninekawa esion eht ,gnar lleb gnolruf eht sa og ot llenk htaed A
dworc eht draeh eH
tub sesroh desu dah yeht ,tsriF
tub rehtona rof edutivres fo mrof eno paws dluow eh ,seY
deips néhC ,srab leets kciht eht hguorhT
.mlac saw dnim sih ,eelem eht tsdimA
,dael eht ni llits saw eh dna dessap gnolruf enO
lla ta efil on saw yrevals no tliub efil a tuB
.erom ecno gnikirts raeY weN fo xamilc-itna eht
snoissessop dezirp rieht
hteet sih dettirg néhC
raeY weN esenihC saw tI
.etarepsed eht fo egitsev tsal eht si epoh tub epoh etarepsed a saw tI
.dluow eH .flesmih eerf
ylisae nac yeht dna liat rieht fo kcilf eno tsuj htiw nem llik dluoc yehT .ecnanimod
thgie rebmun eht ,thginoT
.tnemevalsne sih fo mrofinu eht saw tI
.tsellams eht fo eno gnieb etipsed
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,mih sdrawot yaw sih dehcni néhC
”nogarD eht fo raeY ehT“
,telpord elgnis a otni desnednoc egar sih llA
,ytied dednocsba na ot reyarp ni fi sa ,ylgnignol pu dekool eH
dluow eH .erom ecno maerd ot flesmih dewolla dna
,ecnarbmemer ni trap dna htiaf ni trap
.niaga dehgis eH  .nosiop eht ffo gnithgif ta regnorts tsuj saw eh ebyaM
.duorp srotsecna sih ekam dluow eH
.ezeerb yraurbeF eht ni ,ylirrem tsomla ,ylevitpeced gnitaolf
.msilobme na dnuora doolb ekil ecaps cibohportsualc eht otni demmarc dah sdnasuoht ,erafhguoroht worran siht nI
tceles ot ,seiceps siht deerb ot yaw a dnuof dah
.rehtaew eht morf ton tsael ta
- tnednelpser dna dehctertstuo sgniw
.derudne dah eh gnihtyna naht esrow raf hsiugna fo smaercs deirc dna rehtona fo smra eht ni emraaK sih fo thguoht eH  .mih ecarg yad eno dluow enutrof doog taht dehsiw ew woH
.kcart eht ot ecnartne niam eht sa devres hcihw draytruoc delbboc a otni tuo denepo noos sgnidliub ehT
,reve sa ,dna ssecorp eht desylatac dah gnireenigne citeneG .elbarisednu demeed erew hcihw esoht edisa tsac ot dna stiart ralucitrap
.sepoh s'néhC hguorht tuc ti ekil ria eht hguorht tuc ydob ehtil sih ,gnilppir selcsum gniw htiW
thgie rebmun ykcul saw eh spahreP
,gnireffus saw nogard gnuoy eht ,gninehtgnerts saw lavir sih sa dnA
.nogarD eht fo raeY eht fo trats eht eb dluow yadot taht denimreted saw eh
rehtegot werd spil rieht
,gniog erew yeht erehw wonk t'ndid eH
dna ytilibon fo slobmys
.egnahc yllanif dluow kcul sih emit eht saw won spahrep dnA
.daeha tnemrot fo raey rehtona
,erom ecno bom eht ta nwod decnalg eH
.detatipaced eb ot ydaer srotpac sih fo sdaeh eht gnimoceb syoub eht ,delworg eH
,lleh otni gnidnecsed saw ehs ,saw ehs legna eht ekil ,sey tuB
- tnempiuqe eht gningiseder ot dehcterts t'ndah stiforp
rehgih neve edam erew sseccus rof sdrawer eht ,duts ot tuo tup gnieb yb egaenil a gnitaerc fo ezirp eht htiW
.mrof sih gnioottat rebmun eht ta dekool eH
.mih ta dekniw ehs erows eh
,og ot sgnolruf owt htiw taht wenk eh sa dloh ekat ot detrats cinap fo gnileef A
***  .thginot mih rof ykcul eb ot evorp
nogard deruoloc-ybur
.traeh sih ni peed morf feileb fo esnes a pu gnillew ,edit eht tsniaga kcab deppir evloser sih sa deusne noos elttab a tuB
- erofeb fo sevren eht dna stbuod eht erew enoG
.laog sih sdrawot dellup ydob sih ni elcsum yreve sa
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.emraaK saw ti ,rof gnithgif htrow gnihtyna saw ereht fi tuB
,shtaed rieht sdrawot gniltruh lla ,oot gnillaf lla ,snogard neves rehto eht deips dna dnuora dekool eH
.yrgnuh erew yehT
,epirtsepuL flowkcaP yb
,poows ot deunitnoc eh sa tnaliassa sih erongi ot deirt néhC
”nogarD eht fo raeY ehT“ saw sihT     .lla retfa
,sthgis eht htiw gnitsrub ot dellif
”nogarD eht fo raeY ehT“ si yrots s’yadoT dna
.erac t'ndid eh tub
.evivrus wohemos dluow ydob sih gnipoh
,etunim a edisni deneppah osla ecar hcaE
.nosirapmoc ni emorhconom dna detsur
,sgniw sih fo taeb hcae htiw mih no gniniag saw nogard ehT
.mih rof erew sreehc esoht dehsiw eh woH
.drawrof flesmih gnilleporp
.noissapsid rieht detcelfer sniahc sih sa sraet erom dehs seye siH
.traeh sih fo taeb yreve htiw gnisaercni mutnemom sih
.ynam fo tnemom tsrif rieht derahs
,snevaeh eht ot despmilg eH
yeht sA  .eerf eb ot dneterp ot modeerf eht dah yeht tsael tA
?mih nopu yresim hcum os depaeh dah hcihw ecalp emas eht eb t'ndluoc
.snretnal dna setik gniylf erew ohw nerdlihc llams fo puorg a no desucof eh ,flesmih tcartsid ot deen eht gnileeF
wons retniw eht fo noitacoffus teknalb
.noitca eht fo eceip a lles ot deltsoj nemssenisub sa tnetopinmo emaceb noos gnitekraM
,serutaerc tnednepedni era snogarD
.thgin eht ot efil erom gnivig ,ria eht detaemrep tnemeticxe eht sa
.yks eht dna dnal eht revo
.evol ro cinap saw ti rehtehw ot sa
.trops fo eman eht ni lla saw ti dnA
,esruocecaR thgiE ykcuL ehT
.nerdlihc evah ot
.dnuorg eht otno tuo dewolf ti erofeb wolf doolb teg ot etarepsed ,meht koohs eH
,erofeb enod dah srewoprepus sA
,ssenippah dna tnemeticxe siht ,ytivitca fo evih siht yleruS
.redrah etepmoc snogard eht edam ylno dah siht dna
.mroforolhc fo lluf lewot a htiw gnitteuorip anirellab a ekil ,sesnes sih gniggum erofeb niks sih pu decnad noitasnes ehT .ydob sih fo edis thgir eht no ria dloc fo tfaw a tlef eh ,sthgis sih dengilaer eh sA
.ruoloc ni hcir sgnoras edam-dnah ot sreweks no dekooc yatas hserf morf - elbanigami eraw yreve gnireffo srekwah htiw ,lausu naht delbmuj erom erew yeht ,thginoT
,denevretni dah snoitnevnoc s'yteicos tub lautum neeb dah gnileef ehT
,noissimbus fo raey rehtonA
,sgniw etaciled reh ni nogard gnuoy eht pu depparw emraaK sa dnA
denworc eb dluow eH .duts ot tuo tup eb dna lrig sih niw dluow eH
yenom fo tiusrup eht saw ti
.thgir sih ot espmilg rehtona elots neht ezirp sih ta dekool eH
.ti dnatsrednu t'ndluoc eH
.erutaerc tneitnes a rof efil on saw hcihw
.meht hguorht thgir deraes evah dluoc ti gnittuc os erats a ;sgniliar detsur eht hguorht ezag yleets a dexif eH
.devresed ylimaf sih nerdlihc eht eris dluow eH
.stiart elbarised erom fo tiusrup eht ni seneg rieht htiw gnitnemirepxe
.noitartsurf suoivbo ni ria eht gnihsarht tsaeb lufituaeb a was dna tfel sih ot ecnalg a deksir eH
.ykcul gnieb morf raf saw eH
lavir sih fo liat eht sa daeh s'nogard gnuoy eht dnuora detarebrever dnuos wolloh ehT
,yrotagrup sih fo ssenllud eht ot tsartnoc nI  .sreziliuqnart eht fo tceffe eht sa gnisufnoc dna gniyzzid sa
.nigeb ot eud si yalpsid krowerif tnecifingam a erofeb sdnoces lanif eht ekil ,noitapicitna htiw deuqip saw erehpsomta ehT
.ytic dlo eht fo steertskcab derettulc eht hguorht yaw rieht gnidarap reldnah dna nogard was siht dna selbats eht morf klaw trohs a saw esruocecaR thgiE ykcuL ehT
hgih edor lavir sih sA
.luos eht dessergorp ton dah ecneics fo ssergorp ehT
.erutrot no tliub eno saw emraaK tuohtiw efil a dna
.ytilituf reuqnoc dluow evoL
.ria retniw dloc eht fo tsalb gnitaralihxe eht leef dna sgniw dehctertstuo reh pota tis ot
,luos sih gnitnuah snoitalulu rieht
.doolb ni dehtab neeb dah ytic elohw eht fi sa saw tI
,yrotciv fo airohpue eht ni espalloc lavir sih was eH
.terger gnilppirc fo imanust a ni denword eh
,evititepmoc erom osla saw ti
.sgnidliub fo ezam eht hguorht yaw lufelod sih edam eh sa ,emahs ni trap ,raef ni trap ,dewob daeh sih tpek néhC
elbarapmoc si htgnerts rieht ,gnilppir selcsum htiW
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.tnorf ni mih dekcom yllacitonpyh
- noitcetorp deen t'nod snogard tuB
,nruter ni delims ohw ,emraaK fo espmilg a thguac eH
,redrah desucof dna pu dekool eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
won ygrene otni detrevnoc gnieb saw raef eht tub
,deppart eb reve lliw I emit tsal eht si sihT
.tsrif hsinif ot detnaw lla yeht gnirusne edirp 'snogard eht htiw
.tneve eht retfa sresol eht morf raeh ot stnaw eno-on neht tub ,dworc eht fo smsagro ytpme eht yb tuo denword saw niap siH
.tnatsni na ni evol ni nellaf dah tub semit wef a reh ot nekops ylno dah eH
.woleb sdnuoh gniyab eht fo tip eht otni knus eh enots a ekil ;teef ytnewt ,teef net ,teef eviF
.eye sih ni pu dellew raet ylenol A
.noitavlas rof yletarepsed gniyarp fi sa rehtegot kcuts sgniw rieht
eht hguorht detfird cisuM
.aibohportsualc fo esnes a htiw sthguoht sih gnitullop
.eerf flesym tes ll'I yad eht si sihT .thguoht eh
.tsiser ot elbissopmi saw ti tub nwod kool ot ton deirt eH
;nem fo sevals eht emoceb dah snogard taht tnaem osla tI
.yltcefrep murd eht fo dnuos eht gnitnemelpmoc tnemevom eht fo mhtyhr eht
.dnim sih ni dexif ytuaeb reh tpek syawla dah eh
?yaw sih gnidaeh saw dna sdnob reh nekorb
.noissimbus yb detades rewop rieht ,sreziliuqnart yb dehsiugnitxe erif rieht
.eerf eb ot erised eht saw desnes néhC taht efil ylno eht tuB
.odnecserc sti dehcaer dworc eht fo esion eht sa ffo og skrowerif draeh eh ,eelem eht fo tsdim eht ni ,retal sdnoces neetfiF
,snomed eht evoba esor dna evol eurt eno sih ekil ria eht decarbme eH
.tsol saw elttab eht wenk eh traeh sih ni peed tub thgif eht gnithgif tpek dna sraet eht kcab thguof néhC
.tsegnorts eht tpek tsuj dna meht derb dah yeht ,neht kcaB
.erauqs eht ni ssender erom saw erehT
.ytilarom fo noitagen eht ni detluser dah hcihw
regnorts taeb traeh sih gnikam saw eriseD
,epirtsepuL flowkcaP yb
.llef nogard eht ,denepo part eht nehW
,daeha gnigrof erofeb nogard gnuoy eht ta kniw a dehsalf eH
.ecar eht rof detcepxe srotatceps 000,03 eht rof gnitiaw dna demirp ,srelles erom doots ereht ,segnirf eht dnuorA
.noissimbus fo dnik wen a otni sepoh sih dna traeh s'néhC gnitaeb
,ylsuoiruf gniknilB
ta puC ytiC tekcoR eht now eh fi tub ecnahc edistuo na dah ylno eh wenk eH  .traeh sih reh evig dluow eh thgin eht saw thginot dna
.enola emit erom gnidneps fo deracs ,sraet erom dehs eH
.lortnoc rieht tressa ot
nogard eht gnilliw fi sa
owt htiw enecs emas eht ees nam sselemoh eht dna OEC eht neht tuB
.tsaf mih ot pu gnihctac nogard neerg tnednelpser a was dna daeh sih detlit eH
,sdrawno ylnrobbuts delialf dna
dna rethgual fo dnuos eht draeh eh ecnatsid eht nI
.sseccus dna yrolg
.detiaw ynitsed sih ,mih evoba teef ytfiF
,ysae reven si gnihtyna od ot snogard gniniarT
refas osla saw trops ehT
.mih flugne ot gninetaerht spart ekil shtuom rieht
.niaga modeerf hcus leef ot denraey
.esle gnihtyreve ekil ,deganam-emit saw nuF
.denimreted saw eH .snolat rieht ot yerp llaf ot gniog t'nsaw eH
,meht erofeb sgip dna swoc htiw enod dah yeht sa ,snamuh tuB
.yad lamron a no hguone gnilffab neeb evah dluow ytic eht ,llec sih fo srab eht ta yldiprot gnirats ot desu os nogard gnuoy a oT  ***  !emac eh ereh ,sserp diolbat ehT
- yldedraug sepolevne der ot no gnihctulc erew yehT
.smrots fo tsekcalb eht mrof ot yks eht denekrad yrlavir rieht sa ,saes suoutsepmet morf pu deppihw ecidnuaj a
,flesmiH doG fo taht ot
.demaercs dworc eht ,mih woleb teef ytfiF
.dniw eht ni yltneg gniyaws erew yehT
.kcab efil remrof sih evah ot gnihtyna evig dluow eH
.rotnemrot sih ,rerac sih
.tnetni fo tnemetats a saw ti deveileb ohw ynam erew ereht ,ecitcarp eht denmednoc emos hguohtla dna rewop fo sgnippart eht fo trap si ecar a fo noitagujbus eht tuB
,ysatsce ni gnilwoh
.devoleb sih yps ot emit tsal eht rof pu dekool eh ,sniahc eht erofeb gniwob erofeB
.detevoc eb dluow dees sih ,yrtsudni evititepmoc a hcus ni dna
;derudne netfo dah eh sgnitaeb ydoolb eht hguorht dna
,thgin eht otni dna muidats eht fo tuo mih gniylf
.sredluohs sih ni poleved ot detrats dah pmarc lufniap a ,sdnoces 01 nihtiW
.reh teg ot thgif ot evah dluow eh os
,yllacinam sgniw sih deppalf eh ,retsam sih ffo gniggurhS
.ecaf sih otni dehcte nosiop ,néhC ta kcab decamirg eH
.reh rof denraey eh woh ,hO
.luos sih gnirethguals trats ot tbuod fo seiranecrem eht gnitivni
t'ndah ehs ,yleruS
,dehcatta erew snogard elamef eht hcihw ot sniahc eht deips eh
.reh nioj ot pu esor eh sa yoj fo smsyxorap gnitaeb traeh sih
.neeb yllaitini dah ehs naht mih ot resolc raf demees ehS
,reh htiw raos ot gnibmilc tirips sih ,ylluftsiw maerd ot flesmih dewolla eH
.suoicarov erew yehT
.thgif ot desiop saw ydob sih ni elcsum yreve
ecalp siht ot nekat neeb dah eh erofeb ,dah ecno dah eh efil eht fo ffihw a saw tI .ni dehtaerb eH
thgir eht niw dna cilbup eht yb deroda eb dluow eH
.dnim sih htiw skcirt gniyalp saw noitsuahxe eht rehtehw ot sa erusnu ,deknilb eH
?nwot emas yrev eht ton
.trapa sgniw sih desirp yllufecrof eh sa raos ot detrats eh ,desaercni sgnileef esoht sa dnA
.srotcetorp eht saw morf noitcetorp dedeen yeht gniht ylno ehT
.seye fo sriap tnereffid
,erauqs eht fo elddim eht nI
.noitinifed fo rettam a neeb syawla sah ssergorp neht tub
.emraaK teews ,emraaK .niaga dehgis eH .thgir sgniht tup ot ecnahc eno sih saw thginot taht wenk eh dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
reduol werg esion eht ,esruocecar eht dehcaorppa
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf
.saniter sih ssorca niap fo skaerts gnihcrocs ,niarb sih otni kael ot nosiop fo smaerts eht gniwolla
tfel flah a dna gnolruf A
.erusnu saw néhC ,ecivres s'raey rehtona fo tcepsorp eht ro ecar eht fo niap eht ot eud saw ti rehtehW
.thgie rebmun ykcul saw
.evila tlef ytic eht
.kcart eht dnuora yllufecarg cra ot detrats eh sa kcab sih nwod hsur modeerf fo dniw eht tlef eH
srenniw deerb srenniW
,ylevil tey wols saw ssergorP
.gnineve elbatiforp a eb ot erus saw tI
.emoh dellac eh egac eht ot nruter ot flesmih deidaer eh erofeb
.kcart a dnuora sgnolruf flah a dna eerht ecar ot meht gniniart enola tel
,seye wolley dloc htiw rehto hcae ta derats yehT
now eb ot dah snogard elameF
.sesnes sih delgnit seldoon dna stuntsehc tsaor fo tnecs eht elihw ,rettahc fo kcartdnuos a htiw ria
***  .flesti gnitaeper ylerem saw yrotsiH
,sesnes sih edavni eruliaf fo lobmys eht gnittel ,dehgis eH
,rednow desumeb ni ti ta derats eH
snogard owt eht sa ecarbme gnimraw s'evol ni devlossid sdnoceS
,reldnah sih fo thguoht eH
,ecnalg yratulas a flesmih gniwolla ,ytuaeb reh ta pu dekool eH
,lla meht peek ot detnaw yeht woN
,sucof ot nageb dnim siH  .ykcul eb dluow
,dettirg hteet htiw etag eht hguorht deklaw eh sA
.esuac relbon neve na dnuof dah 'sgniK fo tropS' eht fi sa saw tI
.snevaeh eht dna htrae eht neewteb dnik sih fo sderdnuh neeb evah dluow ereht ,oga sraey wef A
?mih gnikcom yeht ereW ?siht saw tahW .sdirbyh nogard-namuh gnitaerc yb snoitanimoba rieht derehtruf t'ndah yeht ,yleruS
eh tub dewollof noos srehto ehT
.evol ot pordkcab erem a dworc eht fo soob eht ,ssik lausnes a ni
,tiforp rof ylerup derb erew yehT
.ytic eht hguorht detaslup taht efil fo sniev gnitaerc ,der lanoitidart ni dekcedeb erew elpoep ynaM
egral a deips néhC
loot a sa noitagujbus desu yeht
ytuaeb eht laever ot efil otni dedolpxe neht hcihw
.ffo nekat yltnatsni dah trops ehT
.llats eht ot teef sih gnidnib niahc eht ta nwod dekool néhC
,dlrow rehtona saw siht yleruS
dluow thgie rebmun eht taht depoh eh
seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY .0102 ni kcab teeMruF ytiC tekcoR eht rof yrots siht etorw ohw
ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
eht hguorht ,taeh remmus eht fo noisserppo gniyolc eht hguorht ,selcyc ranul evlewt hguorhT
.llits doots emit lla ,ria eht ni tem yeht sA
.néhC ot neila yletelpmoc erew - noitarbelec fo sllems dna sdnuos
.tif ot mih rof redro ni daeh sih evoba sgniw sih etavele ot dah eh os dna
.emahs dna tnemssarrabme ni daeh sih deirub eh erofeb
.esle gnihtyna neeb evah dluoc ti eveileb ot evïan saw eH
.ynitsed ot resolc dna esruoc eht dnuora deppihw eh sa
erusnu saw eh tub sseniddig fo gnileef a htiw hsawa saw daeh siH
.srettam gnipleh yldrah saw ,edis hcae no thgie rebmun eht htiw derediorbme ,raew ot decrof saw eh tekcaj niluaprat yvaeh ehT .ti etaivella ot od dluoc eh elttil saw erehT
.etaf sih ot dengiser dna edutivres sih gnitpecca
.tnemtrapmoc ynit sih ni dehcnuh syad sseldne eht fo ,ssenilenol sih fo mih dednimer tI
,denut dnim siH .emraaK fo
.mih fo tnorf ni ecifide etercnoc eht sdrawot denrut eh erofeb dworc eht fo thgiled eht ta kool erom eno flesmih dewolla eH
.enadnum eht fo sepoh eht revo suoirotirem ytuaeb
,gnicar lanoitnevnoc naht retsaf ti saw ylno toN
.nihtiw denoitats si taht rewop eht ot tnematset neddih a
.dnim sih no deoottat emraaK fo egami eht
.evom ot eerf saw ti tub mih ekil dekool ti wenk eH
.esruoc eht gnikram sdrallob gnitaolf fo seires a yb detautcnup ria ytpme
.dnoces elgnis a ni yrrauq rieht ffo kcip dna snevaeh eht morf poows ot meht swolla ecarg yrotaderp rieht elihw
.trapa llaf wohemos dluow sknil gnorts eht taht gnipoh ,moderob ni dna ytilituf ni ,yltnalahcnon ti ta dekcik eH
fo ecnerefni citnamor a depoleved
.raw rof ydaer ,daeh sih dewob eh sa ssenrettib sih gnireuqnoc htmraw fo gnileef a ,delims eH
.enil hsinif eht detutitsnoc hcihw muidop eht no doots
syekcoj rof deen on saw ereht sa
.sllats ynit rieht nihtiw dessurt ,sevitpac rehto eht sdrawot elbats eht fo tuo dekool dna dehgis eH
;kcart eht ta derats eH
taeb a deppiks traeh sih dna tem ylkciuq seye riehT
.namuh tahwemos dekool sgel esoht lla dnA
.enipus os dekool syawla yeht tub ,eerf eb ot denraey reve yeht rehtehw derednow eH
.stnemele eht tsniaga detcetorp dna pu depparw lla erew yeht ,swor tneiciffe ni degakcap yltaeN
.ssenisub gib neeb syawla dah gnicaR
.niap ni gnimaercs won saw nogard eht ni elcsum yreve tub ,noissap ni gnimaercs ,teef rieht no erew dworc ehT
.mraw dna tnaidar os dekool reven dah yks yraurbeF ehT
.ni nword ot srehto eht rof liat sih htiw ekaw yppohc a gnivael
.raey eht fo ecar suoigitserp tsom eht gninniw rof ezirp eht saw tI
,noitaroda fo evaw eht no
.doolb sih rof gniyab dworc suorovinrac eht evoba teef ytfif dednepsus ,egac gnitrats depmarc eht otni dedaol saw néhC sa woleb delkniwt ytic eht fo sthgil ehT
,repeed dekool eH .niks denekcalb s'thgin hguorht gniraet ruoloc fo sracs was won dna
.enacirruh a fo eye eht ni gniwollib slias sselesu ,nugeb neve dah yeht erofeb derit erew sgniw siH
.etaf elbongi na tem dah erutaerc elbon ehT
.nugeb neve ton dah ecar eht
.snoissergsnart sih rof htaed raen ot deppihw neeb dah eh semit eht lla fo dna derutpac neeb dah eh yad eht fo thguoht eH
.mrots a ni seilfrettub ekil gnirettulf rednerrus fo sgalf eht
- nogard gnipoows a fo thgis eht sa noitcnitxe ot nevird erew dna tnadnuder emaceb sesroH
,kcen sih ot swap nwo sih detcennoc taht latem eht ta dekool eH
- steerts gniltsub eht ,yadoT
.efil yraropmetnoc fo ecneitapmi deirruh eht rof detegdub hcihw
,ycamerpus rieht egnellahc erad ohw esoht lla ot yrotaro na si erif fo yrotcaf rieht ,elihwnaeM
.prahs-rozar sesnes sih
.erudne ot dah snogard lla gniniart detnemiger eht ot eud
.kcen-dna-kcen won erew yeht dna
.won mih gnivird erew noissap dna tcnitsni ylno tub tluassa eht evivrus dluow eh deyarp dna hsinif eht ta derats eH
epirtsepuL flowkcaP yb
.dloc sih denrut tI
.niaga ecno evil dluoc eh dna revo eb dluow lleh sih
.yks sselerutaef eht ta pu dekool néhC
.eviecer ot gnitiaw ,dehctertstuo dna daorb sgniw htiw
,sesnes sih detcefni ssam gnihtees eht ,despiart eh sA
.yrutnec ts12-dim eht ni snogard htiw detnemirepxe sruenerpertne