,trats daeh dnoces evif a reed eht evig uoy ,pu enoyreve enil uoY .reed a teg uoy
”.t’ndluow I .ecalp sih s’siht ydobon llet ton dna elgnim
.daeh sih detlit luaP ”!xaw toh tub
”uoY roF kcaP taerG eht ni ecalP a s'erehT“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     .seliM erew
,revird eht ni flow dezingocer
”tnet eno dedeen ylno“ dna
.tnedicni tuohtiw tekciht eht dehcaer seliM
,snamuh fo htrow riaf etats elohw a loof ot hguone doog neeb d’eh tnaem eno tahT
,resolc dellor ’gniog‘ dna ’og ot ydaer‘ neewteb emit fo dlohserht ehT
,eno saw eh tuB .flowerew a gnieb htiw od ot gnihtyna dah taht gnihtyna gniod ro gnilles eb ot mees t’ndid ohw
.naD dias ”,gnola gat oG“
,llew ,derahs mih htiw sevlow eerht eht taht terces on saw tI
,ereht neeb syawla evah elpoep reeuq ,niaga rof
.ereh tog I ecno citamotua eb d’ti thguoht I neht dnA
,fo thguoht enoyna eman tsrif eht erew uoy dnA ?ecneirepxe evah
,rewsna sih gnitrats erofeb tnemom a pil rewol sih dewehc seliM ”,llaf tsaL“
".rehctawdrib ro rekih a t'nsi syad eerht tuB
.eseht fo not a dah moM“
”,thgirla ,thgirlA“
,ti dnuof eh woh saw taht fi ,neht tuB
’,elcnu‘ eht pord luaP detsisni dah seliM ”,pup lleW“
tuoba deirrow m’I“
:kcen ruoy fo ffurcs eht fo llems eht ni
!yllaer ,hcnar eht ffo emit tsrif ruoy s’ti ,thgiR !hO“
.flow a gnimoceb yb
,denrut tog tsrif I nehw ,nwolb saw dnim ym hcum woh aedi on tog ev’uoy
si snwo neve kcap eht ekib eraps ylno eht dna ,eseht fo eno edir ot nrael ot elihw a sekat ti
mih no sdnah eht fo owt erus saw eh tub gnihtyna llems t’ndluoc eH
.kcaP taerG eht fo sdnuob eht dnoyeb dna tserof eht ot yaw eht lla tnew ti dne eno tA
kcab meht dednah luaP
?dworc deticxe na“
.ti eveileb t’ndid eh dias naD hguoht
,gnilworg ,degreme seliM ”,yhW“
,seilf worc eht sa gnol os ton saw ereht etuor rieht fi dna
,yrtnuoc eht ni sevlowerew eht lla no gnihtemos llup ot detnaw I dna ,tnega na erew I fi dnA
.derednerrus ehs ”,did ew sseug I“
,gnitfihs retfa neve
,snoino ro etalocohc ot setoditna deen thgim tub
”?melborp a ereht sI“
,sreppilc cirtcele htiw demra tsilyts ruf a saw erehT
”?ekil yllaer s’ti tahw tuoba wonk ot stnaw eH“ "-
”.gnihtyreve dna taes liat eht rof rab yssis eht no tup I
,slwoh degarne ,gnilrans ,dipar ’seliM raeh
hcraeser htlaeh gnitacovda stelhpmap dna
,seiceps evisavni lanoisacco eht dna eeffoc fo sesomreht no gnitsaef
.gnol yats dna etal trats dluow taht gnineve remmusdim a dna
,srae sih dettap naD ”,nwod mlac ,kO“
.ffo tuc erew seciov rehto nehw tfel saw taht ecnelis drawkwa eht otni llef dlrow elohw eht dna
.kcab eht ni luaP degdun gnihtemoS
teknirt emos noitartsurf gnisaercni htiw dna gniusrup yldeggod
,seldnac detnecs erew erehT
”?pup ,thgir lla gnileef uoY“
enoyreve nurtuo osla tub“
gloBcM kahtfU morf ”,sruoy sa hcum sa tsuj semoh ruo syortsed gnikcarF“
ew t’nerA“ ”?wonk uoy
.dnoces eht yb desufnoc erom gnitteg saw naD
.pu kaeps mih draeh dah luaP tsrif eht saw hcihw
.setoditna etinoca gnidulcni ,tik dia tsriF
.hcrop eht no mih htiw tuo sgab eht evah ot detnaw t’ndah eh tuB
”,tuB“ ”!kcap eht tsuj
,semitefil ruo ni ,ecnatpecca fo llewspu ralimis a eton ot llew si tI
”.ti ekil dna ti yrt
.sekib eht tuoba egnarra ot sgniht eht lla erew ereht taht retfA
.ksa ot rebmemer ot deticxe oot saw luaP seman esohw
.won rof teg ot gniog saw luaP noitanalpxe eht lla yltnerappa saw hcihW
,reve sa citsimitpo sa ,reve sa lacinyc sa
”?kcap sniatnuoM enipucroP eht fo ,yrogerG seliM uoy erA“ ’.A ,zemrelliuG‘ daer taht gat a htiw ralloc a erow eH
teg reven d’eh deirrow saw eh gniht eht edam tI
.melborp a saw taht kniht ot demees ydobon os
,ho …tfel eh dna ,saw I erofeb neve ,kcap eht fo trap eb ot desu dad ruoY“
,nos reh fo erac ekat ot teg
”?yllacitamotua neppah...“
,t’nod I“ ”-kniht t’nod uoY“
,meht gnoma atnegam ro ,neerg ,eulb cirtnecce erar eht htiw tub ,etihw yltsom
,tfarc fo epyt yreve saw erehT
.suoicerp erom eht lla mees
.pup ,no noisiced a esab ot tol a ton s’tahT
.repsihw a neeb dah ti tuo denrut ti tub
,evraH elcnU degguh moM ”,lleW“
.eno ytnewt tsael ta eb ot evah uoy ,ffo tsriF“
.deddon seliM elcnU
,ti htaeneb yltcaxe tsomla saw ta kool ot gniyrt htob erew yeht esuoh ehT
,dnah sih ni eldnac eht ta ,delffab ,nwod dekool luaP
.denialpxe .A zemreilluG
,eno dlo s’seliM
,sezis dna ,smrof ni
”,yadhtrib reh rof erehwemos morf meht redro ot desu daD
,rae detniop a fo edisni knip ynwod eht ni sgniht fo stros lla daer ot gnisimorp
?rof ksa enoyna dluoc noissimrep erom tahw dnA
,htuom sih denepo luaP
,seye s’luaP tem seliM
,ekoms etihw fo sduolc gniweps
I nac woH ?evael I nac woH
,rehtegot emoc thgim skcap eht lla taht
.mih htiw evol ni lla erew ew taht saw ti ,yag lla erew ew taht t’nsaw ti yas d’I .od …rO .did ew
ekil sgniht dias taht draobretsop no slainomitset revo ’!woN ytiradiloS‘
!pup eht yllaicepse ,rehtohcae barg uoy
.yrt ot ecnahc a teg t’ndid
.sneris odanrot ekil ,delwoh yeht nehw ,gnilwoh dna
thgir ylno si tI .noitarimda dna
,htimskcalb a saw erehT
?ot evah eh did ,flesmih deksa eh ,neht tuB
”?neht ,deticxe s’dworc a fi llet yeht od …woH
.srelevart wollef erew yehT
yltsom tuB .flow fo
.tfihs ot efas eb ot ti wenk dna
’rotalihinruF‘ eht saw ti dias ni emoc dah rettal eht egakcap eht ,sehsurb owT
.srac rehto tsuj t’nerew
,tnega .M.P.E fo .B a ot gnihton yas t’noD
,llet dluoc luaP sa raf sa ,ydoboN
”?od ot em tnaw uoy od tahW“
snoilivap wohs dna
,oot ,gnignahc tpek noitacol ehT
,ti ekil t’nod dna ti yrt I fI .ytilibisnopser ym eb ll’sneppah revetahw
,esuaceb ’selcnu‘ sa lla meht nwonk d’eH .dnob a
daer taht rennab egral a saw taht morf ssorcA
rof snobbir riaf etats eht lla dniheb tfel d’eH
…noisiv citehporp a ekil tlef tahw morf seye sih detreva luaP
ts1‘ dna ’raeY A hcus-dna-hcuS ewE ezirP dr3‘
,nus eht fo ecnemehev eht morf seye rieht eraps
’,elcnu‘ fo yteirav emos sa mih ot decudortni neeb tniop emos ta lla dah ohw
.saw eh deticxe woh tuoba eltbus eb ot tseb sih gniod luaP dnuof gninrom ehT
setalp repap htiw od dluoc uoy hcum os ylno saw ereht—
naht ylnialp erom ti yas ot suovren oot nigriv a ,eh saw woh dnA
,ecaf sih revo gnikat morf nirg eht peek ot thguof luaP ”,ma eruS“ ”.sklof ruoy naht pirt siht tuoba deticxe erom er’uoy epoH“
.noziroh eht revo
”?deT rebmemer uoY .kO
snaej fo riap eraps a dna
”?ydaer s’erif eht ecno ,stiucsib nevo hctud ekam dna wets pu taeh annog m’I“ ,nitraM dias ”,hU“ ”?od
”.htiw revo ti teg retteb ,emoc ll’I
.emankcin taht tuoba tlef eh woh erus t’nsaw luaP ”,hU“ .dias naD
!lanummoc saw tI !derahs nwod ti desahc ohw enoyreve taht
ot nwot tsohg dna ,deewelbmut ,accuy hguorht thgin yb yaw rieht gnillems
.don a htiw kcab meht emoclew tub gnihtyna od ot
.snilboG fo noitageleD ellivsnikpoH eht fo
,emac yeht snoitavreser eht morF
.tekcaj s’seliM fo rehtael eht otni delffum erew
,semit erar eht tuoba thguoht luaP
,sVR elbatrofmoc dna snav elbisnes ni
,llew ,dnA .tsil ycnegreme ruoy ni ekaL tlaS ni mrif eripmav taht rof rebmun eht tog uoY
.noitpo ylno eht ton er’ew“
.uoy wonk ot teg ot gniyrt snamuh fo lufdoohrobhgien a tuohtiw gnivil a ekam uoy tel
dewolla hteet dna sdnah htob—raw fo gut saw tneve txen eht tuB
.A zemrelliuG dna mih drawot epols eht nwod delbmut dna daeh sih revo decnuob tI
..rof snalp eht era tahw ,hU“
.regnol on sih erew yeht won
.taht ta eno namuh-non A
.rood neercs eht hguorht seye sih tem dna denrut evraH elcnU
.ekil leef uoy reveohW
”!yllaer ,moM ,enif s’tI“
.stekcop sih ni sdnah
.esruoc fo ikahK dna
.tsoh eht ,tuoba gniklat er’yeht flow eht s’taht sseug d’I“
.seliM ot denrut eh sa taht fo erus ssel hcum dekool ecaf sih ”,oS
.srae suoludercni dekrep luaP
.sehcaer eh noisulcnoc eht dna
”.og uoy erofeb hcnul elttil a rof emit tog tsael ta lla uoy ,lleW“
,detsisni nitraM ”!stiucsib nevo hctud tuohtiw gnipmac og t’nac uoY“
.ecno ta noitcerid yreve ni yawa hcnilf ot deirt ydob s’luaP
,etteragic a ruoved ot noitats sag eht fo edis eht dnuora pets derad ohw
,sffilc edisaes ytliug eht morf ,emac yeht detlep-kciht dna yggahS
,spirts ykrej eucebrab redic elppa fo talf draobdrac a now yeht tub
,dniw eht otni secaf kcits
.thgis fo tuo saw eh litnu
,puP“ .yldeticxe detpurretni naD
”,htron pu tekcit sub a uoy teg nac eW“ .derettum naD
drazzilb a retfa neve gninrom samtsirhc ot pu dewohs
.sevil reeuq dna elpoep reeuq fo
,semag lavinrac erew erehT
.gniyats fo aedi eht htiw ecaep ekam ot deirt yltsenoh d’eh raey taht ,flesmih deraehs d’eh loow ,dettink d’eh fracS
srelevart yna ta ylsuoirepmi erats dna
.yletelpmoc ni hcnar eht dewons dah
”?…si kcap a tahw s’taht...“
”,rehtaew eht no eye na peek ot tnaw annog er’uoy ,woN“
.ega dlo sih ni suoicipsus tib a nettog s’eh tub ,did evraH“
,rettam t’ndid taht tuB
,ot klat ot sevlow dnif …tsuJ“
sevlow fo dworc a
,tbuod eht fo tifeneb eht
”!ees annaw uoy revetahw tuo kcehc nac ew ,melborp on ,haeY
ekib eht no yllautca saw eh won esuaceb ,ko saw dednal dah sdnah sih reverehw taht lufepoh ,dniheb morf naD ot gnulc luaP
.derutnev luaP "?snaem hcihW"
,renniw eht si gnihtyna steg ohw eno ylno eht ,yaw sihT
,tnemom a detiaw dna
rednu gnitteg mih tnaw t'nod I" .detcejbo seliM
,selbmarb eht fo raelc teg ot gnilggurts snamuh owt eht ees
.sbuc rof neve ,sedir on
,yrd dellems yehT
?ecalp thgir eht dnuof yllaer d’eh fi gnirednow efil sih dneps eh t’ndluow
”.seno eseehc ohcan eht er’yehT“
wobniar a ekil yaw eht lla mih denokceb
,sevlowerew yb ,sevlowerew rof
”!si taht ,pu tnet gnikcuf siht teg reve nac I fI“
.denialpxe nitraM
’,citsuR‘ dellac nwot a saw detsisni sngis esohw ecalp a tsap meht dnuow dah daor eht emit eht yB
.mih gniklats tbuod tlef eh—
retawhsid fo nib eht morf revo deklats seliM
,mih ot gnihton erew esoht
.dias yllanif ehs
,egassap tsewhtron eht rof hcraes eht ro sehsur dlog deliaf yb denodnaba tfel snwot morf
”…hu …lla uoy t’noD“ ”?lla
.tnet a fo epahs eht demussa savnac delpmurc fo elip eht dna
”,sliaf esle lla fI“
,lerriuqs delaecnoc
”,erofeb eseht nees ev’I“
?eh t’ndid ,yrt ot dah eh tuB
setib revil deird ezeerf eseht fo gab a uoy teb I
,seliM dna luaP naht rellat tey ton erew llaw kcolbrednic dehsawetihw eht no swodahs degde drah riehT .t’ndah eH
,kcab depol stnap gniggoj ni flow nworb gib a erofeb gnol t’nsaw ti tub
”.rof em swonk ydobyreve gniht eht otni denrut siht taht etah tsuJ“
.did skcap gniht a saw siht gnimussA
.erehwemos semihcdniw egral fo ynohpylop tniaf eht dna
,denrut tog I nehW
,seliM ot ,derewsna naD
”.naem I tahw wonk uoy fI
.koot eh htaerb hcae regnorts werg
,yticirtcele detsat reven dah taht snibac ni srellewd ,srenol
.su erew yeht esuaceb
.tlep krad a gnoma dexim sriah revlis tsrif eht ekil ti otni gnipees
”’?kcaP taerG‘ a dellac gnihtemos tuoba dnuora gniog sromur yna raeh uoy“
,tuo meht peek ot tneiciffus demuserp stnemnrevog namuh llaw fo selbmahs eht fo ecnaifed ekil-etoyoc ni ynam
"?ko ,emit elohw eht em gnidrocer uoy fo htob tnaw I"
,noitats sag eht dniheB
.dleifnroc fo serca tub gnihton saw esoht dnoyeB
.era yeht erehw em sllet tsuj tahT“
.flow dna namuh sa ecnereffid a krats sa
.dehsaba tib a dekool ,sehtolc sih eveirter ot kcab dettort nitraM
nosmirc fo sehcuot eht deciton tey t’ndah ti ,yenoh fo roloc eht gnieb ot desu saw thgil ehT
?kcap sih eb dluow revetahw ni ecalp sih eb dluow revetahw rof kool ot erehw mih llet dluoc yeht fi tahw esuaceb
,gnilwoh dna gninnirg
,ruf trohs revo stiusmiws dna sessalgnus
.saw eh dlo woh ksa t’ndid
.bmuht nwo sih ffo meht dekcil
,morf yhs dluow ylzzirg a neve taht
.enohptrams ffats a dah .A zemrelliuG tub ,enohp elibom a denwo reven dah luaP
,seirrow sih morf yleritne luaP tcartsid ot hguone tsomla saw tI
”-FATS“ drow eht fo trap
.ti otni mih detliug nitraM dna naD tub ,luaP rof eno teg meht tel t’ndluow yllaitini selliM
”!gnitrats er’yeht ,hsS“
.taht morf tnemegaruocne devresed-llew ekat ot
.yaw eht fo tsom su ekat ll’taht ,831 SU tih ew llit tsew daeH“
.ria eht ni wap a htiw nus gnittes eht kcolb ot deirt nitraM ”,onnud I“
,eert ydnah a morf sgnignoleb dna sehtolc gnah ot
.nwod gniog gnihtemos saw ereht detrats sromur“
,ytngierevos labirt fo snoitaloiv lausac dna stnega .M.P.E fo .B fo gninialpmoc snoititep gniraeb emos
,seiratubirt sa selkcirt tserab eht gnirehtag srevir ekil
?thgir ,yad eno kcap eht ot emoc ot tog ev'yeht esuac
,yrenif rof hcrop eht fo renroc eht morf gnilgnad sthgil samtsirhc daed-gnol fo gnirts ro
,dnal etavirp no gnissapsert er'uoy
.emoc lliw sevlow eht ,hguone raelc
,gnoS aynoT ,regnirratS
”,neht ,era yeht ereh ,pleW“  )2 fo
”.ris ,ereht revo si seliM elcnU“
,meht ta gnisruc deunitnoc seliM elihw pu seloptnet eht dleh naD ”,eveileb t’nac I“
,eerf gnieb ,thgir nwo sih ni flow a gnieb fo
,rednad lamina ot ygrella na evah llits ot hguone etanutrofnu esoht rof oopmahs laemtao gnihtoos fo noitartsnomed a saw erehT
.eb ot ti tsurt ylluf t’ndid seliM ekil dednuos ti tahw saw gniht kcaP taerG siht gnimussa
,namow a dna nam a ,elpoep owT
”.dellik teg t’nseod reed eht
.ffuts adnik siht llems dluoc I ylneddus dna
.skcurt doof ynam os
:ekil stnecs fo yteirav a ni
?kcap a gninioj rof tuoba erac uoy gnihtemos yllausu ton s’taht ,ezilaer uoy“ ,dias naD ”,kO“
?taht ekil gnihtemos otni tif ot yaw a dnif ot desoppus
”.kcab sraey elpuoc ,esactun taht ot denetsil ohw ydobemos s’ti ylekil eroM
”?huh ,melborp eht fo trap s’taht
,deknilb luaP ”?on ,hU“
,noisserpxe deifirret ,delffab
?thgir ,sesserdda fo tsil taht uoy evag eiluJ“ .pleh did hcihw
,eucebrab remmus ro ytrap yadhtrib
.kcap taerg eht revo lla
tnarraw a em wohs rehtie uoy os
snrecnoc s’evraH ”?ton s’ti fi dnA“
”,gnitlusni elttil a si ti sseug I naem I“
.dessarrabme yllauqe tub
”-ydobyna t’ndid ,hhhO“
,dray tnorf s’enoemos ni seceip ot tsur dna oga sedaced ytingid htiw eid ot dewolla neeb evah dluohs taht snogaw noitats ni
,grubseluJ ni sag rof deppots yeht nehw ksa ot ecnahc a tog yllanif luaP
taht yas erad dluow enon
”!naem I tahw ton s’tahT“
”.si taht ynam woh wonk neve t’nod I hcihw
"?uoy no enohp ruoy tog ev'uoy dnA" ".haeY" "?ereht nI"
,syawhtap eht evoba gnurts ,shtoob eht edisni ,selbat eht revo
”?rof gnidaeh er’ew gniht siht s’tahw ,oS“
”.sllabwons tsuj ti
.deksa d’eh erofeb naht retteb yna gnidaeh erew yeht erehw dootsrednu eh ekil leef yllaer t’ndid luaP
.siht ni seveileb eh ,gnihtyna ni seveileb eh fi ohw
”.ekib eraps …a eb d’ereht demussa I sseug I“
.sdnalnoynac eht hguorht sdrawkcab
.gnihsulb t’nsaw eh deyarp luaP ”.thginot
”,nam ,detfihs er’uoY“
,riaF s’dlroW ogacihC 3981 eht nwo ot gnimialc ,etodcena sseltniop ,gnilbmar ,gnol a rO
,ebyam llor repap teliot a fo ezis eht
”.uoy ni flow eht htiw pu werg uoY“
,ygoloce ni deveileb yeht rof
!taeb m’I taht wonK“
.tcejbo t’ndid os dna
,degnarra edisni gnihtyreve gnitteg dna sgab gnipeels tuo gniyal
.niaga emoh rof dnuora nrut dna meht ta ssuc ll’sevlow tsom dna ,pmac decirprevo na tsuj ylekil n’erom s’ti nehT“
,sevlow rehto eerht htiw maet utpmorpmi na demrof meht fo ruof ehT
.nihton ro enola ffo og t’noD
.hguone eltbus neeb t’ndah taht yltnerappA
”!tnaw uoy fi won thgir og nac eW“
.ecarbme na otni evraH dellup seliM
,ereh syawla erew yeht
,tcatnoc eye edam luaP nehw deticxe dekool meht fo enO
”?ko ,tuo teg dnA
.pu worht ot gniog saw eh ekil tlef ti
,emac yeht stresed deggaj eht hguorhT
yks tnecrep ytfif ylesicerp fo dlrow a ot desu efil elohw sih devil dah ohw ,luaP oT
”.won rof kcul fo tuo er’uoy oS“
…t’nac I fi kcap a fo trap eb ot gniyrt fo aedi eht ekil
,tuo denrut ti ,erew erehT
.elttil a xaler flesmih tel luaP
,liof munimula htiw derevoc swodniw gnicaf htuos ,egieb ot detsalb-dniw tniap wolley
…eh nehw rehtohcae evah ot su detnaw dna ,smelborp traeh
”,rettam t’ndluohs tahT“
,erehwyna pu tes uoy tel ,dnuora evom uoy tel ti—sevlowerew rof boj nommoc yrev a saw ti naD ot gnidroccA
.kcap 'selcnu sih nioj ot esohc eh ,si taht ,gnimussa
”.ecalp elohw siht snwo ohw yuG
”.ekil yllausu sepyt renol ssenredliw eseht nibac cisab adnik eht ekil skooL“
ylno hsirep taht stsaeb eht od sa ylsuoyoj evil ot ydaer
,desaerc sworb s'seliM ”.siht …rof
,wap no ro toof no rehtehw yleerf delevart dah srotsecna rieht sdnal hguorht speej pu taeb gnivird
,ti ekam nac yeht fi ,yrtnuoc elohw eht ni flowerew yreve detivni ev’ll’yeht won yB
.sserp ot nottub hcihw luaP wohs ot emit dah .A zemrelliuG taht yawa hguone raf saw ti ylikcuL
”,no gnah lleW"  ”?tahW“
ysub oot lla erew yeht hcihw retfA
”,eteP ,thgirla s’tI“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT
.ti dnuora pu tup sepor dah dah
”.tniop eht was yllaer reven I“ .desum luaP
’,sdnik lla fo sretfihsepahs‘ rof nevah a eb dluoc ti gniugra
si kcap ruo“ ,mih derussa naD
?su tuoba draeh dnA
,llams yrev ylneddus dekool sraey rof demaor d’eh erehw erutsap fo serca ehT
rehtom sih ot klat ot sraet hguorht elggurts rehtaf sih draehrevo d’eh
,seliM naht deyonna ssel dednuos nitraM
eht tahW“ .gniticxe sa tsuj saw tahT
.rewsna na dnif ot elbanu devorp naD .deppans luaP
saw taht em fo trap a saw erehT .ti od
”!nuh ,gnitiaw htiw gnorw gnihton s’erehT“ ”.dellac s’ti tahw tsuj s’taht naem I“
.straeh rieht ni slairt natirup fo yromem rettib eht dna staocrednu rieht ni gof dloc fo llems eht
”,od eruS“ ”?etuor a tog uoY“
.sselteknirt ,dehcaorppa nitraM dna eh sa dias seliM ”?tahw wonK“
”.dnal eht fo yal eht teg ,tib a dnuora klaw ot aedi doog a ylbaborP .worromot llit trats t’nod stneve lautcA“
daeh nwo sih edisni neve
.gniliar hcrop eht revo yawflah gninael saw moM
,lwob attocarret nekorb a fo mottob eht ekil ,meht fo lla dnuora pu yltneg devruc taht yellav a ni yllaniF
.dniheb dnoces a naht ssel
”?wonk uoy ,ecalp a gnidnif
ll’I taht diarfa ton m’I“
.ot detnaw eh nehw kool dluoc eh gnitadimitni woh ynnacnu saw ti dna—
.snroht yrrebkcalb derehtiw fo tekciht a ta deddon ,porctuo na dniheb detlah seliM ".su
.deddon evraH ”,doog sdnuoS“
neht dna ,denetsil ohw flow rehtona otni gninnur si ekat d’ti llA“
,rood nehctik eht ediseb llimdniw nedoow erutainim derettab lanoisacco eht ylno htiw
ylla na eb ot ylekil erom ot
,lareneg ni ,regral demees wohemos eH
.meht ni tfihs ot citsale fo ytnelp htiw sehtolc nwes-dnah
,serauqS egroeG ,regguR .P
”,llems t’nac snamuh ,tiaW“
.efil sih fo tser eht lla dah d’eh naht
detnioppasid erom eht lla luaP edam tsuj tahT
flowffats eht dna seliM gniliat flesmih dnuof luaP woh saw hcihW
uorag-puol dna smaet delsbob
.tnirpwap s'nooccar a htiw dengis ylno saw taht
erusiel ssalc-rewol demahsanu ni xaler ot tnetnoc lla
suoiciled erew yeht nitraM ot timda ot evah dluow eh dna—stiucsib dna wets fo etalp sih tpecca ot dah luaP os
,seotatop dekab-eciwt fo sgnipleh wef a tuohtiw yaw rieht no og ydobon dednamed taht ytilatipsoh fo esiug eht rednu
elbakatsimnu emaceb ti—
.gnihtemos htiw yawa nettog d’yeht ekil dekool htob yehT
”…ekas s’kcuf rof hO“
”?wonk uoy ,luferac eb
”!neppah yeht nehw citamotua eb ll’ti eveileb nac I erehw emoc ot sgniht erom yna fo kniht t’nac I dna
,sllih tsae eht sdrawot revo
hcrop eht no gnidnats
”-tsuj ot lufetarg eb dluohs I ,wonk I ,wonk I“
,seliM elcnU dias
,tnuh a ekil s’ti
,sdoow eht drawot htap eht nwod erot yehT
.suolucidir tsom saw sevlowerew fo noitciped mlif hcihw no snoinipo gnorts dna stlep dehcaelb nus gniraeb
semag lavinrac eht fo eno ta
,tsafkaerb dehsinif yeht sa tnet eht dehcaorppa flow yerg krad mils a ”,em esucxe ,hU“
,on oN“ ”-t’nod uoy fi ,ti eldnah nac eW“
a dna galf ekilfracs wolley dna eulb a gniraew yb dehsad reed A
,sevlowerew erew ereht dnA .flow dna
,thgin otni gnidnapxe meht denigami eh dna gninehtgnel erew mih dnuora swodahs eht
.seliM ot sgep txen eht tuo dleh eh ”?thginot
,esuoh denodnaba ,dworc deticxe
”!pu eno ekam tsuj d’yehT“
,emac yeht tsewhtron deltneg-niar eht fo stserof cilardehtac eht morF
,gnoleb dluoc eh erehw kcap a fo smaerD
eldnac skrazO :rohcirteP eht nwod tup naD
,skceneltrut ralvek gniraew erew yeht ekil dekool tI
?thgir ,flow a ekil evil dluoc I erehw kcap a dnif dna tuo og ot ,efil ym lla
,ereht yenruoj eht no saw eh ,tey ereht t’nsaw luaP fi dnA
,klaw ysae na ta tekciht eht rof edam dna ffulb eht dnuora dekcud redael kcap eht ,taht htiW
”.stnega uaerub htiw
nosaer emos pu ekam si od d’I gniht tsrif eht neht
sessub loohcs dnah-dnoces ni ,emac yeht tsaoc dessik-tesnus eht morF
yhtapmys fo serugif ot deliver dna deraef eb ot sretsnom morf
”.yawyna sniatnuom eht rof tuo ekirts ot emit eb ll’ti ,revneD ssim ot ti evael attog ew emit eht yB
,senilepip lio fo noitnem yna ta slworg nruticat rieht ni stnecca gniraedne
”.eiluJ ,esrepsid attog s’flow A“
emeht siht no seirots suoiverp dnif nac uoy dna
,knat enaporp a ot pu dekooh egrof elbatrop ,livna ynit
,aremac no er'uoy" ,dekrab neht
.evah t’ndid eh srewsna eroM .s'seliM rO
.sevlow rehto htiw gnilif ydaerla ,enil gnitrats eht rof dedaeh nitraM
,ffo denrut smsinahcem gniggir eht lla htiw yldesoppus
.emoh tfel I ecno citamotua
.sriatspu elbmarcs ot dah eh ,yawhgih eht nwod gnimoc senigne eht draeh d’eh nehw oS .wonk t’ndid eh
”!ti ni tnaw I tahw gnirb nac I os ,reliart eht gnillup saw ohw eno eht m’I dna“
,yrgnuh ,ecreif eht taht saw ti
.adanaC dna ocixeM ni neve ,yrtnuoc eht revo lla
”-staerht gnikam trats uoy erofeb
,rotavele niarg denmednoc dna yrotcaf denodnaba morf
.raelc deggard gnieb saw eh nehT
.mih rof tnaem ton ylbaborp gnihtemos ot gninetsil ,sparts eht no llits sdnah sih tub
.redrob odaroloC eht revo tsuj
dennirg nitraM .gnidnatshtiwton tserkcab deman-ylgnitlusni ,saw taes eht worran woh dna
,yeksihw fo elttob s’htnom txen eht tcelloc dna nwot tseraen eht no dnecsed ot esiugsid namuh gnimuser ylno
.ylitsah yawa dekool flow regnuoy eht dna
,pukcip gnissap a fo deb detsur eht ni edir selim wef a fo ecnatpecca tnelis gnikat emit ot emit morf
taht si siht fo tniop
’,renniw‘ a eb t’ndluohs ereht dna
.kaeps ot os ,tnet eno eht dedeen ylno thgie fo kcap elohw rieht …llew
.eerf-revlis %001 deetnaraug ti fo lla ,yrlewej edamdnah saw erehT
.emit ni tsuj waffug a kcab dekohc nitraM
taht“ ,pirt siht semit evif dexif ydaerla ev’uoy taht ekarbdnah a xif ot evah uoy ezilaer uoy nehw hgis uoy yaw eht ,dehgis seliM ”,yas tsuj s’teL“
.etsaphtoot ,hsurbhtooT .DI dna tellaW
,thgiarts yrev pu gnidnats sevlow erew erehT
,meht fo tsom hguoht ,dnal eht fo renroc yreve morf emac yehT
.yppup deticxe na ekil gninnirg dna ,tekcaj sih rednu ,flesmih detfihs ydaerla saw seliM tub ,lavorppasid ffurg gnitcepxe ,seliM ta ,yllufepoh ,kcab decnalg lla nitraM dna ,naD ,luaP
,ebut latem llud a ees ot emit hguone tsuj dah luaP
,gniggaw sliat ,dekrep srae
sohcnop ekilrennab dna stah pu-taeb ni srekihhctih ylenol
snoitan rezinoloc-erp hcihw tuoba ,gnikniht lufhsiw dna noitidart laro fo tliub
,tnega .M.P.E fo .B ylhtraenu emos
.tellub revlis ro enabsflow erofeb
,nwod kcab tog eh emit eht yB .tseug a sa
,nioj ot emoclew eb d’eh rehtehw
.tsael eht tnemeganaM ecalupoP namuhartxE fo uaeruB eht gnitsurt si kcap eht ni sboj ym fo eno
”?sedir pu tes annog er’yeht taht“ ,derednow nitraM ”,kniht uoY“
.esoht fo tuo esu hcum gnitteg no gninnalp t’nsaw eh—
,smra s’rehtohcae ni thgin eht dneps ot gniog erew yeht rehtehw fo tnarongi llits—
,fo wenk ehs kcap yreve fo sesserdda dna snoitacol eht dekram ylgnikatsniap dah moM hcihw ni ,salta elbadloF
aremac a dah eno dna
.eb dluohs eh dias yromem s’luaP naht
.yawa mih ekat ot ydaeR
,tnerap a eb ot ecnahc tsal sih rof ,snoitpo tcerid ssel dah daD
gnignits erew seye siH
,srellet enutrof erew erehT
lla er’uoy naem I“
.kcap eht fo traeh eht saw eh
.nesir tsuj ylno dah nus ehT
.meht htiw etag eht ot tuo deklaw stnerap siH
”?uoy fo lla ot taht od
.stnet reeb erew erehT
,scilyrca tnecserohpsohp ni noom eht fo sesahp htiw detniap
”,reed eht no s’galf ehT“ .deksa luaP
.derevoc ti tog yeht“
.gnihtemos ezilaer ot demees eh llit
.mih revo ssuf ot dah moM
evraH elcnU guh ot nrut sih gnikat erofeb
.emit emas eht ta elttob a ni kroc a dna rekcarcerif a ekil esion a saw erehT
,htiw denrut tsrif d’eh ohw
,selcycrotom eht dehctaw
.rehtona eno htiw nommoc ni dah yeht taht lla dloh dna
.ereht tuo luferac eb ot mih llet dna elgna eerged evif ytrof a ta ffo gnikool dnats ot dah daD
.hctac t’ndluoc luaP esnopser rehtona dah yehT ".evael ro
niaga retne reve ylno d’eh hcihw tub ,sraey neetenin revo rof sih
,ekil ,eb d’ti thguoht I sseug I
.goD fo ecioV eht no ereh thgir
”.dnim ym no tol a …tsuJ“
?taht od ot gniyrt detrats lla ew fi ,ereh era sevlow ynam woh htiW“
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
”?thgindim dnuora ni nrut yllausu ew sseug I“
.ylper ni deddon ylno eh tuB .dniheb tfel d’eh
.ruf tub gnihton ni
.gnikirts si ,semitefil ruo ni ,yrots ni eb ot dewolla si flowerew a tahw ni egnahc ehT
”!xes evah lla uoY !yag
”.secalp reggib dna reggib dnif ot dedeen yeht dna gniworg tpek tnuocdaeh eht sa sseug I
.seye sih dellor naD ”,og
,eseht od ot desu kcap dlo yM .llew hA“
reppus nosinev gib a
”?gniht dab a s’taht kniht uoy ekil dnuos uoy od yhw“
drah os gnihguoc saw eh dna
”thgiR saw opyliaT“ rO
.noitasrevnoc ni peed erew
.t’nsaw luaP ”,enif m’I ,hU !hO“
.hcaer t’ndid thgilnus eht erehw swolloh dedahs eht lla dnuof snoitasnednoc gninrom revetahw fo dna ,ytsur dna
”.ereh eno teg t’now yeht
,pu til ecaf sih neht ,noisufnoc ni deknilb naD
!erolpxe annaw uoY
?neht tahw ,ti od t’nac
,no gniog saw tahw ees ot elbissopmi ytterp emaceb ti erehw
,ylluferac yrev dias naD ”,taht sI“
:moordeb eht morf kcapkcab dna gab leffud eht debbarg eH
.dael eht koot seliM
.sblub tnemecalper rehto on neeb d’ereht nehw
,hu ,uoY .sredurtni emos
,deksa neeb yeht dah
,tsud ,srehtael daor ,enilosag fo llems eht saw erehT
,emac yeht sesub nrow-tresed nI
,nitraM ekil ,tsom tub
rof kool ot tahw wonk t’nod I dna deneppah t’nsah ti dna ereh m’I won tuB
,raewrednu ni emos ,strohs citelhta ni emoS
”.meht htiw ereht thgir eb ll’eW
neht esuaC .ediced ot gnivah si em seracs tahW .haey...“
,ecneinevnoc fo skcap gniworg ni rehtegot dnab ylwols yeht dluow neht
”.oga htnom a ekil deretne evah ot evah uoy ,dnoceS
.yawevird eht no selcycrotom ruof erew ereht
.enog erew yeht dna tsap saw ti ylneddus litnu
.tuo dnif ll’ew esoppuS“ .deggurhs seliM
”.nagihciM ni kcab egarag eht ni skcolb no pu s’taht dna
,htuom s'naD fo renroc eht morf sbmurc yrettub dehsurb seliM tniop eno tA
neeb dah ti ,tsael ta ,tnemom taht roF
daor eht no srac rehto eht taht
.wap s'luaP otni enohp nwo sih desserp seliM ",kO"
,stnega .M.P.E fo .B"
llems yb yaw ruoy dnif dna
.ecalp s'naD ni flesmih enigami dluoc luaP gnimussA
”,ta dehcaerp teg ot yaw siht lla edir t’ndid eW“
.sdeerb detaoc yggahs ro egral rof dednemmocer saw dna
eno citsur a ylbainednu ,gnidliub elgnis a ylno was luaP hguoht—
,revo snaem on yb si yteicos ni ecalp lufthgir ruo rof thgif ehT
,tuoba gnikniht diova ot gniyrt neeb d’eh noitseuq rehto eht ,doog hO ”…I“
,sdneirf doohdlihc eht ,setamkcap eht tuoba
,nruticat dna mirg
,tsud daor dna enilosag rednu neve elbakatsimnu yleuqinu
”.gniod er’ew tahw dnatsrednu t’nod I“
”…tsuj I ,taht ekil ton on ,oN !oN ?tahW“
,esoprup gnirevaw fo tnih tserem eht ta
.reliart esroh a saw ereht rehto eht tA
ykrej morf gnignar taem detardyhed meht fo tsom ,skcans erew erehT
,lleW“ .nrub srae sih tlef luaP
ekib s’nitraM dniheb reliart drah eht otni derewol kcapkcab ,desuap luaP
,tleb sih fo edis eht otni dekcut trihs olop neerg a dah eH
",sepols eht no pu sraluconib htiw enoemos neeb s’erehT"
:ytinummoc yrruf eht fo gnihton yas ot ,niaga ,si hcihW
”?gnol os meht gnikat s’lleh
”?puP ,em htiw gnidir uoY“
.gniht elbaplap a saw meht fo ezis eht erehw yaw a ni
.dnah gnirussaer a pu dleh seliM ”.yllautca
”,og attog t’nod uoy ,yenoh ,sthguoht dnoces gnivah er’uoy fi wonk uoY“
,ladem ’ecalP tsriF‘ eht tub
,egarim taeh fo remmihs eht morf sevlesmeht stsohg ekil gnigreme ro
,redluohs reh dezeeuqs daD
t’nod I dnA .ot tnaw I fI
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ni deklats yltpurba dna esion deniap a edam seliM tub
”.meht yrt dluoc uoY
:sthgil samtsirhc fo sgnirts erew ereht tuB
,mih tohs seliM elcnU kool eht dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.kcab gnikool tsiser t’ndluoc luaP
etarepooc ot spool retseylop dna selop ssalgrebif elbixelf eht decnivnoc yllanif seliM ”.ebyam ,sbuc roF“
.yenruoj siht gnikam saw kcap nwo rieht tub yna taht desirprus neeb evah dluow
,emac yeht htron derennam-dlim eht morF
.pup mih dellac llits ohw tub
.srehtnaP retaW fo dnaB nrehtuoS ,issanaT morf
.naD dna seliM ot esolc kcits dna“
,llis eht no sdaeh tser ot nepo dellor swodniw
,nevig s’eh srewsna eht
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf seigolohtnA ni
noisserpxe hcae ni erehwemos gnignol
,liat ro rae detcepxenu eht laecnoc ot hguone gib
”?haey ,siht ekil nrob erew uoy ,lleW“
.sseug I ,oot nitraM
.kcap a si kcap taht yaw eht fo trap eb
,sehtolc s’nitraM pu dedlof naD
.gnidliub eht fo renroc eht dnuora ylprahs dekool seliM
.draeh eb dluoc esnopser on taht os enigne sih devver eh erofeb evraH ta
”?uoy rof melborp a“
,wols ylgnizinoga
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
pirts worran gnol a dna raelc tpek neeb dah dnuorg level ot gniht tsesolc ehT
.redluohs sih no dednal wap s’naD
-sih htiw nur dna tfihs dluoc eh neht dna ,noom gnisir a htiw
,tpurba neeb dah daor eht ni egnahc ehT
,srae rieht dniheb lwob tsud eht fo sgnivael eht dna ruf nwolbdniw htiw
.saw ’esactun taht‘ ohw nialpxe t’ndid eH
”!gnitnuh og yeht nehw slamina llik ot snamuh rof enif yltnerappa s’tI“ .deillar seliM
htiw su pleh dluoc uoy depoh ew yllautca“
.renepo nac dna ,revirdwercs ,sreilp htiw efink ytilitU
,retaw nelots dna dnas era snoitadnuof esohw seitic etercnoc sselitip eht morf
”.ees ot deen I lla s’taht“ ,dennirg eh
,redisnoc d’uoy thguoht ev’d’I“
,pu kool ot pool savnac eht hguorht gep eht gnittif no desucof oot saw seliM ”,lleW“
,obmika smra ,doots eH
,lleh ,evil sevlowereW
,demees ti ,seliM dna naD .desserd teg flow detaefed eht depleh dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
hsurbegas dna enac fo stekciht eht erehw
,floWcaM boR yb
gek eht gninnam flow ehT
"!hcum gniod t'nsi uoy ees t'nac I gnidneterp ruoy dna
.despalloc eh erofeb
.rohtua eht yb daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,gniht elohw siht tuoba yhsif
”?huh ,emit si yllaer ti sseuG“
,rehtohcae dehctaw yeht yaw eht yltrap saw tI
...“ ”…tsuj dluow ti ,tnet eht ni ,thginot taht gnipoh adnik
”.ti esahc uoy neht dna
.mih htiw ro ,rehtohcae htiw tpels ew
…naem I“ ,dekrab naD
”!thgindim tsap s’ti dna yad lla gnivird neeb ev’eW
,ecalp tsrif ekat t’ndid yehT
.rohcirtep fo stnairav lanoiger fo kcar elohw a dna
.ma I fi wonk …t’nod I“
yaw siht“ ,detroter naD
ot elba gnieb fo diarfa ton m’I“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.su erew yeht esuaceb
,wap a ro dnah a rehtie rof dezis sloot
.deggir eb ot desoppus t’nsaw taht
,tnecs eht yltrap saw tI
.ti fo derit ydaerla saw naD ,neppah ot tuoba saw revetahW
.dah reve d’eh kcap ylno eht dehsinav meht gnomA
,dias yllanif naD ”,lleW“
tcnitsni dna tnecs sselnu ,wef a ylno tub
,mrof namuh ni neve gnihtolc deniadsid ohw emos ,skcab rieht revo sratiug htiw emos
”.tcA seicepS deregnadnE eht ecnis sevlow naciremA ot neppah ot gniht tseb eht eb thgim ti neht ,si ti syas ti tahw si siht fI“
.skcap neewteb gniteem siht saw ti neht ,rehtegot gnitteg skcap elpuoc a saw ti neht ,anozirA ni kcap eno tsuj saw ti draeh ew tsrif tA
.ffo emac sksam eht
sdoow eht otni dehsinav reed ehT
.fo demaerd dah luaP gnihtyreve
a snwo ohw flow emos si romuR
,gnitallicso relknirps a fo taeb
”?yltcaxe ,tneve siht rof yfilauq uoy od woh oS“
”!won ,ti did I tsael ta oS
.sdnah reh gnurw ehs ”,seod ti esoppuS“
.gnitnirp-neercs wolley ni elbisiv
,mih dnuora noitcerid yreve ni nepo dlrow eht fo llems ehT
?sklof ruoy ,raf os tahw nees ev’uoY
,sraet dehs ot desufer dna
,nioj ot detcepxe eb d’eh rehtehw
level a htiw ,dnuorg tnecrep ytfif dna
.rohtua eht yb daeR
.dekcap erew sgab s’luaP .daD dias
.pu tes ot devirra ew ecniS"
.yawa denrut dna elituf sa gnitniuqs pu evag nitraM
,nwo ruoy no erolpxe ot ecnahc a evah dluohs uoy taht worromot seliM llet ll’I
tnet eht pu tes eh sa seliM rof sgep munimula gnidloh saw eh won tuB
.eerf eb dna thgin eht otnI .kcap siht …htiW
,tohsrae fo tuo erew nitraM dna seliM
,rehtorb gnillac nigeb dna elcnu gnillac pots ot depoh eh flow eht fo kcab eht ot gnignilc
”.eromyna ,mih evah t’ndid ew nehw
derettam tahw dias eh dnA
”?aedi dab a reeb taht saW“
,emac yeht skaep citsejam-elprup ,denworc-reicalg eht morF
.tekcaj sih no dellup dna dehgis seliM
,ylkciuq dias flow ffats eht
,inohaS ,knupariM ,enrohtwaH .S.J
,detnaw ev’I …ekiL“ .dessefnoc luaP
.pots kcurt eht nihtiw morf naD dna nitraM deveirter seliM
,redluohs eht no rehcnar denrecnoc eht deppalc evraH elcnU
.gniht elohw eht tsoh ot dereetnulov
”.pup ,sgniht eseht fo yna llems t’nac snamuH“ ”?tahW“
”uoY roF kcaP taerG eht ni ecalP a s'erehT“   yojne esaelP
,devaw yehT .raf oS
,gniwolb saw dniw eht ,gniraor saw yawhgih ehT
,taht tegrof ton od ,ton naht seye erom ni ,demrofsnart evah oot ew tub
”?enog s’eh fi ,taht fo trap eb I nac woh oS“
.su no ecnallievrus gninnur
,deggurhs naD ”,ti dekcap nayR“
.noos eb dluow yeht tub
,ruf sih revo norpa evitcetorp kciht
”?gnihtemos ro uoy knaht yas og“
”,kcap gnitnuh a ekil ,rehtegot krow htob attog ev’uoY“
thgin taht socat fo sdnik tnereffid erom dah luaP
noitazinagro esnefed lagel namuhartxe tiforp-non a saw erehT
:ytinummoc yrruf eht ni flowerew eht fo ecalp eht fo gnihton yas ot si hcihW .ymene na naht
htiw dne ot desu tI !tnuh a sa ,ti od ot desu yeht woh s’taht dna
.uoy htiw moor eht ni reywal a tog uoy ssel ,reve
,seiteicos rieht ni
.deoottat eb ,gnikaeps yllacitcarp ,t’ndluoc taht stsehc ro sredluohs otni snrettap suoilleber gnivahs
.kcap a fo ytimixorp esolc eht ni deeps pot ta gninnur elbatrofmoc erew stcnitsni rieht fi sa
”uoY roF kcaP taerG eht ni ecalP a s'erehT“
.redluohs s’seliM no daeh sih dial flow redlo ehT
.nioj ot detnaw eh rehtehw ro
,redael tsuj t’nsaw eh ,wenk reven uoy esac ni ,lleW“ ”.haeY“
.tuo tnew dna derekcilf raeppasid ti ekam dluow tcejbus eht gniciov yllanif taht epoh ehT
.si ycavirp ot thgir
…lla uoy t’nerA .onnud I“
trats tseb d’eh neht“
.sevlow sa kcaP taerG eht ta devirra yehT
.taht od dluoc I fI
.eno taht ni etapicitrap ot tog luaP dna—
.B :yrots siht fo gnitirw eht ni noitatlusnoc dna ecivda dedivorp ohw esoht ot sknaht laicepS
dah ohw flowerew yerg-delzzirg ,ralucnuva na ot ,doohyppup ot kcab dnim sih tsac luaP ”?erodoehT elcnU“
,hguone duol lwoh uoy fI
”?em rof ecalp on s’ereht dnif ot ylno ,yaw eht lla og I fi tahW
.detrons nitraM ”,on lleH“
,godpeehs gnikool-gums a fo erutcip eht htiw
.ffins latnemirepxe na nekat d’eh hcihw fo
,eci fo gab a yub
”.em rof pu gnitiaw gab gnipeels a tog I ,nom’C“
”!lla si ,yllis tsuj s’tI“
,stoob gnikih dezitpab-dum dna strihstaews dedooh depirts-kcajrebmul ni
.taht fo duorp llits saw eH
timda ot evah d'eH
.revil feeb deird-ezeerf ot
epoh eht no detacixotni dna ,ruf rieht ni srewolf htiw lla tub
,luaP emac lla meht gnoma dnA .ysae saw ti
.egnar niatnuom dna snialp neewteb redrob eht ta
mih ediseb ecalp a koot naD ”?tahw ekiL“
,dias eh ”,luaP yeH“
?su fo lla ot gniod won tsuj erew uoy ekiL"
.mih revo dias moM
,fles eurt sih sa
ydaer eht ta droc etuhcarap fo lioc dna renibarac
.srettam flowerew tuoba klat ro
.snel mooz suomrone na htiw
.sehcneb sa evres ot pu deluah neeb dah taht selab yah eht no
,meht neewteb redrob detupsidnu dna
.kcapkcab sih fo parts eht ot dennip d’eh
.uoy tih ot gniog saw noom lluf txen eht woh ot ytirepsorp ot ecnamor morf
,hctid eganiard etercnoc eht ssorca yawhgih eht fo enord eht erew sdnuos ylno ehT
”.oga hguone gnol gnimoc siht was ew sseug I“ .flesmih
etilop oot eb dluow yrtnuoc nwo rieht ,htuos tnagorra eht ni deyats yeht gnol woh rettam on taht tnedifnoc ,egatireh rieht fo trap a hcae llafwons yvaeh s’thgin a fo ecnelis cificeps eht dna
ew ereH“ ”.ssalc .E.P fo tuo gnihtemos ekil ralloc a no dehcattA“ .deffuh seliM
”?reed a saw ti thguoht I“
.segduj rieht neve
,emac yeht spmaws tlas dna suoyab eht morf suocuar dna keelS
,meht ta gnikool tuohtiw
,emit tsal eno ,eiluJ did suhT
.peels tub thgin taht tnet eht ni gnihtyna did
.ecneirepxe gnignahc-efil yldnuoforp a neeb evah tsum tahw retfa
.tsif reh ni tfola dehctulc galf
.esirnus erofeb taht enod d’eH
”dnob a derahs“
tsuj annog s’eh teb d’I ,waN .ot thgir ylno dna ,gnilwoh nur d’eH
”.morf gnimoc saw laem txen ym erehw wonk dna daeh ym revo foor a evah yllanif d’I lufetarg tsuj saw I
,ylduol oot elttil a ,depley luaP
erehwyna peels dluoc uoy noitpmussa eht no dekcap stik lavivrus erew erehT
.mih tel yeht gnimussA
”.ton ro ti ekil I fi srettam ti erehw tniop eht tsap s’ti sseug I“
,tsehc eht ni seliM tih gnihtemoS
,draoba yats ot drah t’nia tI .puP ,yrrow t’noD“ .luaP ta tub erehwyna dekool dna kcen sih fo kcab eht debbur naD
”?seldnac driew s’mom htiw od ot evah taht seod tahW“
meht rof ecalp a dah evah dluow ,sevlowerew detpecca evah dluow
.sekib eht no kcab deirrac eb dluoc sgab wef a ylno ecnis ,setammaet eerht eht ot tnew hcihw fo tsom
elohw ehT“ .delbmurg seliM
.esnopser s'seliM ylno ,dias yeht tahw raeh ot luaP rof raf oot erew yehT
.tnemnorivne na fo ecnalab larutan eht erotser ot srotaderp gnicudortni ni dna ,noitca tcerid ni
,seirots gniraeb emos
,nepo ylerab tfel rood moordeb a hguorht
.seman rieht htiw sgat dna sralloc gniraew lla
,sksa luaP snoitseuq eht rof emit txen ni enuT
a ta od ot gnihtemos tnaw uoy dna era uoy fi tub ,siht od ot yenom hguone tog ro ,hguone gib t’nera skcap tsoM“ ,denialpxe seliM
,sesserdda kcap ni sniphsup detcennoc nray deroloc hcihw no spam draobkroc htiw ,dia lautum kcap-retni tuoba gniklat stsivitca erew erehT
”?wonk t’nod uoY“ .nageb nitraM
,yllufepoh pu kcirp dluoc taht gnihtemos otni nrut ot yrt srae sih tlef luaP ”,si ereht oS“
.lla ta ton naht esrow syaw emos ni saw hguone tsomla tub
”,eiluJ ,yademos lla su ot sneppaH“
”.uoy rof ecalp a evah annog syawla
otaccats eht ,sreppohssarg eht fo sretnahc eht
”,evraH ,enif eb ll’tI“
”!wonk ll’uoy tesnus yb uoy teb I dna
ot gnidnetni …syug uoy era tahw …ekil naem I“
retal …ekil naem I ,oN“
,dias seliM ”,tnega
,tnempmacne ymra na otni rehtegot deretsum neeb dah noitan eht ni sriaf etats eht lla fi sa woleb tuo daerps skcurt doof dna
’,raeY A hcus-dna-hcuS bmaL ezirP
relttes a eb ot esaec tonnac
”…llats rewohs a ni rehtohcae ’niwolb er’yeht fi ,raews I“
,ecuas etihw ni sllabtaem dna seldoon
.ruoh rep selim 06 ta gnissap erew uoy rorrim a ni gnikool ekil saw tI
.egairram etanoissap tub desivda-lli na edam dah tekram s’remraf a dna wohs god a fi sa
?gniog saw eh thguoht eh erehw ksa ot
.namuh ylluf t’nsaw
.esolc yrev tas naD dna seliM .srab eeffot dna
.sniatnuom eht fo retlehs eht rednu deldduh
”.ecalp eno ni lla su teg ot
.esruoc fo ,gnineppah t’nsaw tahT
gnihtyna pu dekcip at’ndluow I erofeB
,sesuoh fo enil a dexaler ,nwal gnilggurts fo esnapxe na ssorca
?mih ekat dluow kniht eh did kcap tahW
.nwod eson ,derewol daeh
.mih htiw gnieb fo yaw rehtona adnik saw rehtohcae htiw gnieb os
,gnikcapnu erew seliM dna naD reliart eht morf ,dednah neeb d’eh gab eht nwod tes luaP ”,ew dluohS“
,hceeps fo wols dna mlac
,os erew ereht esuaceb
.setats suoirav ot lacol sreywal citehtapmys fo srebmun enohp dna stelhpmap htiw
.retne ot ecnahc a dah t’ndah eh
”!nam dlo ,erac ekat“
.dnuorg ykcor eht ta desruc eH
yad lufetaf a ot ssentiw
,daehrevo revoh ot demees dah yaw rieht evow sekib eht hcihw dnuora sniatnuom eht
,redluohs sih revo dessot nitraM sehtolc eht thguac eh sa dias naD
,smra ni spup gnisrun htiw emos
seert detnuts eht ot lellarap-hgin sdnuorg no slaem yliad rieht deklats ohw
,dnal etavirp no gnirehtag etavirp a si sihT
”?won ecalp hguone gib a“
1 trap( floWcaM boR yb
.revo mih dekconk
.pu gnidnats yb elbmarb eht morf degreme
”.galf eht sbarg ohw eno eht eb ot
”?reliart eht ni kcab tsehtruf dekcap tnet eht si“
,detatiseh luaP ”,tub kO“
,emac yeht yrtnuoc rednuht eht morF
”.kcab teg ew nehw tuo mih wehC“
,wonk uoy ,hguoht nevE
dias dah nitraM ,thgie fo kcap a rof hguone egral—
.tcnitsni tsuj s’tI
,taht detuohs tsuj d’eh deifirret yletaidemmi saw luaP
,raewrednu dna skcos fo segnahc wef A
”,lla ta ton ,taht ekil ton ,hO“
ytinamuh evig ot detnaw yllaer I
stnet dia tsrif dna sdnuorgpmac htiw dellif eb ot ydaer secaps ytpme
.syaw fo stros lla
noonretfa neewteb redrob eht no deregnil ruoh ehT
”.ereh tuo yaw eht lla nori tsac fo knuh yvaeh taht deggul uoy“
,deliver eb ot ,sretsnom eivom morf enog evah sevlowereW
,ylevisserpxe oot elttil a dehcterts naD
,denethgirb ecaf s’nitraM elcnU yaw eht was eh tub
,lwoh a fo erbmit eht ni
,yenom deloop htiw deretrahc
…gnihtyna dnif uoY“
,sretsnom su llac ot esucxe na rof gnikool srekcuf-edasurc detraeh-tihs cibohpocyl yna s’ereht fi tuB“
.dekrab luaP ”!?rab tahw ehT“
erew stsertoof eht llams woh fo erawa erom hcum saw eh
,wal t'nsi ycilop tihslluB namuH artxE fo uaeruB .erac t'noD
...“ ”?thgir ,rehtegot …lla er’uoY“
,yellav siht ni sevlowerew dnasuoht a revo s’ereht taht“
,enoemos dnes ot dlrow eht gnitpmet ekil ,yksir tlef tahT
.eert tsucol detsiwt eht rednu ro
.foorP esaesiD er’uoY naeM t’nseoD seibaR oT enummI er’uoY esuaceB tsuJ taht gninraw ro
dah eh detcepsus eh esuac ti degaruocne eh teb d’I
dlohserht evitcnitsni emos dessorc hcae sa slwoh suoyoj deohce ,sub ni ,elbitrevnoc ni ,nav ni ,pukcip nI
,dliw dna gnidniw ot lanidrac dna thgiarts morF
,niaga ksam namuh sih no tup deen reven dna
”.tey ,uoy rof eno thgir eht nees t’nevah tsuj uoy
.ruf dna ,sgnaf ,elzzum a otni gnippils morf ecaf sih peek ot rettam taht rof dna
.stsil s’rehtom sih morf dezingocer luaP hcihw fo emos
relttes a taht dnim ni gniraeb lla tub
gnihtemos ro evreserp ssenredliw
,fi ro ,taht ton ,kcap a erew ew taht saw
,detpmet t’nsaw eh dias dah luaP fi eil a neeb ev'dluow ti dnA
.tsehc sih ot pu seenk sih dellup luaP