,syug eht htiw tis craM dna ekaJ“
”.esrepsid annog s’eh erehw sediced eh erofeb ereht tuo s’tahw fo aedi na gnitteg eb ot desoppus s’eH
,rohpatem shtruof eerht tsael ta eb ot demees taht yenruoj niart gnol a
.naem uoy tahw s’taht fi ,esuoh ym s’tahT“
siht deifirret flah naht erom dna
yawa eb annog m’I tuB
.t’ndid eh esuaceb ,dias luaP
.stamordnual elbaremunni ot tsol sniats elbatnuocnu fo stnanmer eht htiw dedaf
snoitnetni sti dna yrots eht terpretni ot ,renetsil
.devirra tsrif yeht nehw nees dah nitraM dna eh
”.setib revil eseehc ohcan
,snoitcaer )nitraM(
teg ot gninnigeb saw
.ebab ,ecnahc a dah tsal uoy ecnis syad eerht neeb s’tI“  .no devom dna
,emoh sevlow eseht dewollof eh ti ot ees dluow
.yawyna ti tnaw d’I taht hguone nuf sdnuos ti tub
”haey ,eno taht draeh ev’I“
!wonk ot teg’t sllems s’klof attol a toG“
…tsuj ot gniyrt tub
,wap sih htiw levarg eht ta deffucs luaP
.deksa flow krad eht
”’.eninimef‘ dna ’enilucsam‘ fo yranib eht otni yltaen tif t’nod elpoeP
.rehtom reh htiw reh etinuer ot elba erew yeht os
”.uoy ot pU .ot tnaw uoy fI“
,uoy htiw emoc ll’I“
.knarp a saw siht dlot eb ot gnitcepxe saw ehs ekil luaP ta dekool flow ydnas ehT
?dellac s’ti kniht I ,thgiarts
.detsisni cidem eht
tsuj I .ti ekilsid
”.flowerew a ton m’I“
.tsrif ,ees ot eroM .on tuB
,lleW“ ksa ot woble na no pu flesreh depporp ehs hcihw morf
,woleb erif ,evoba sratS
,srinevuos fo lluf gab htolc elbasuer a mih dednah dna
,sllihtoof eht ni pu deb keerc yrd a yb eb ot devorp pmaC
eht ylluf reven er’uoy oS“
”,em ta kool t’noD“
.suoromuh ylteiuq taht dnif ot demees flow etihw-ylraen ehT
,seigoreip rof denitsed erew eseht
.denrut eb ot gnilliw er’yeht fi
.tsael ta ,yklus dnuos ot ton deirt eh
syaw gnidnif tuoba s’ti
,nugeb s’kcap eht nmyh eht ot ,gnilwoh em nihtiw flow eht steS
,ytrevop yb detarapes srevol gnuoy
,hcihW .flow eht sa tneps I dnoces yreve dekcinap
.kniht I ,eciwt ro ecno ereht nettog ev’I dnA
”.deirt uoy fi dleif eht no em teg t'ndluoc uoy tub
”.enim rof gnikool trats neve d’I d’erehw onnud I
.yrt a sevresed taht aedi na s’tI
.seliM delbmurg ”,lleh hO“
”-hsilgnE elddiM otni denrut ’egaugnal eht sa deredneg emoceb ot detrats taht tub
.me fo yna htiw peels t’nod I“
fo trap lanif dna
.wonk I ,uaeruB eht rof tnemom yug doog eraR
.niaga gnirts tsehgih eht dekcehc
,resolc deppets luaP
!taht htiw gnorw gnihton s’erehT !taerg
.luaP ot kcab noitnetta sih thguorb eH
,ekil ,saw daD dna moM neewteb deciton I ecnereffid tsrif oS .snamuh ton
?snoitseuq ynam os sevlow ynam os ksa ot evah
”.ereh eb attog s’ti ,efas si ecalp yna fi dnA
.flow a sa sdal eht htiw dna namuh a sa seidal eht htiw tis ot sdnet eeD neht dna
.raey txen pleh dluoc eh woh ksa ot eslupmi gnisir eht tlef luaP
.noitativni ni nepo dleh ,rood eht hguorht klaw dluoc eh fi
,deggas slwoj sih dna dettam saw taoc s’flow eht
trihs kcalb yggab a ni desserd erew yehT
.aet fo knird rehtona koot eh
?flow eht sa ti deen ton uoy od oS“
,ecalp sih dnuof dah eh ,thginoT
”!siht fo yna fo kniht I tahw gniyas trats I fi ti ekil annog s’ydobon“
?flow sulp namuh ,lleW“
,dah eb ot gnildduc s’ereht nehw eldduc I
”,ylsuoires uoy evaH“
”?elbatrofmoc erom erehwemos ti tuoba klat annaw uoy fi tub“
”,dlrow eht fo dne eht eb t’now ti tuB“
,deyats evah dluoc eh egaruoc erom dah d’eh fi taht erus flaH
d’yehT .stnemngisnoc dna snoitanod morf rehtegot delbboc ,seilppus lacidem fo redrosid lareneg a saw ereht edisnI
,gum gnimaets nwo sih ta deppal flow krad eht ”,oS“
?snoitseuq esoht gniksa ni tniop eht s’tahw tuB“
.sgum fo riap a otni retaw toh ruop ot emit saw ti litnu
,ylsuoituac derutnev luaP ”,erehw taht sI“
”!?erofeb rednib sih ffo ekat yug a nees reven ,dik ,uoy htiw rettam eht s’tahW“ ,mih ta deppans
.ereht tuo elttil a n’erom ,yecaps ,yffurcS
,taht ta deggaw liat dna dekrep dah srae s’luaP woh was yeht nehw trohs deppots yeht
,noitavargga dna noitceffa strap lauqe saw flow ydnas gnilims ylgums eht drawot denrut ehs ecaf eht
,llems fo esnes ruoy evah syawla uoY .namuh
.ti yned t’ndluoc luaP
,god.ecioveht ta
selbat cincip gnidlof eht fo eno fo egatnavda nekat d’yehT
”.namuh eb ot dah I nehw fles laer ym t’nsaw I ekil tlef syawla I esuaC
.gniws hcneb elbatrofmoc ylgnisirprus a dna
,srae sih derewol dna sredluohs sih desiar luaP
,seye sih deworran luaP ”…si relwoH lepsoG …ehT“
,xoferew a saw nrows ev’dluow eh—
t’nod I ,gnorw em teg t’nod ,hO
.tesnus fo thgil nosmirc eht ni yllaicepse
”,retsim ,tsenoh eb ll’I“
tneps rekrowesac ehT
,yzarc s’eh skniht nam a nehw
.rof doots ’A zemrelliuG‘ ni ’A‘ eht tahw neeb dah tuo denrut ti hcihw ,oravlA dna seliM htiw
sag eht ni etinoca neeb d’ereht esac ni tsuj—
.reverof maor ot secaps etinifni dna
.deksa flow rehto eht
”,uoy dluow nehT“ ”.risseY“
.noitanalpxe laitnegnat rehto emos otni
,flesmih ot neve ,niatrecnu dednuos luaP  ”,sseug I“
.ssenisub ’syad gnimoc eht eb dluow taht ,llew… …kcaP taerG
.rehtona r’eerged eno ot ,seod ydobyrevE
,sthgil fo sgnirts eht
,flow rellams a edausrep ot gniyrt yltnerappa
,flowerew ro flowfiw yas dluohs I sseug I ro
,derahs kcap siht ycamitni fo sdnik owt eht fo taht ytniatrec eht htiw demmuh mih dnuora surohc eht
,noisiv thgin tog uoy nehw tnednepedni gniog droffa ot reisae tol a s’ti dnA
.kcab dloh mih edam gnihtemoS
”!mih fo erac ekat ,saw ti revetahw fo lufecaf a tog pup ehT
,derednuolf luaP ”?tahw sih ,hu ,I“
”uoY roF kcaP taerG eht ni ecalP a s'erehT“
.og ot denrut dna ,noonretfa worromot srieht saw dnatsdnab eht nehw netsil emoc ot erus eb d’eh dias
.tnemssarrabme fo eid dluoc eh erofeb yawa deirruh luaP
,ohw erusnu ,enoemoS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
sesahcrup htiw kcab emac yeht sa srebmem kcap eht ot deddon ehS
,noitcelfer ecnahc fo dnik emos yb ,tpecxE
,rof si rednib eht tahw s’tahT
denrut eh ,kniht ot emit dah eh erofeB
”.laer eb dna ekaf gnieb pots nac uoy ekil leef annog era ,feiler a eb annog era tuo edis flow eht tel ot teg uoy semit erar eht neht
.rednow tub pleh t’nac I ,ekil tuB
.flow a yletelpmoc t’nerew llits uoy
.gnol yats t’ndid flow dlo ehT
.hguor yrev erew stfihs tsrif yM“
,suoituac llits ,dias luaP ”…ees I kniht I“
tsoc nac noitisnart ylluf ot ,namuh tsuj er’uoy nehW
flow ron namuh rehtien
,tsrif era uoy ohw eB
.ylbaresim delworg luaP
.gniyrt tuohtiw meht deziromem ydaerla d’eh taht ysae os erew surohc eht ot sdrow dna
taht deirt yeht esuac ,krow t’nseod yhtapoemoh ykcul m’I
”?thgir ,stcnitsni ruoy
.repap loohcs eht rof tcejorp a ekil dnuos ti edam taht ekil ti yas flesmih gniraeh dna
,lleW“ ”?kcap a evah ton“
saw eh ohw gnisseug dnoces t’nsaw ohw enoemos dluoW
,tsruwtarb sih dehsinif luaP
”.ereh pu kcab daeh I dna gnirps llit ereht yats
”?-dluoc I naem uoY“ .yltnatiseh
ekil sdnuos ti ,eno rof uoy—sevlow rehto fo ytnelP
.reeb fo plug a yb decrofnier saw nub dna egasuas fo pmohc evitalpmetnoc rehtruf A ”.huH“
”.emit gnol a rof rehtegot gniht elohw siht gnirb ot gninnalp neeb ev’I dnA
.nwod elttes dna dnim ym egnahc ll’I ebyam …oS
,ysatnaf eht htiw no yrrac llew sa thgim eh tub gnirussaer saw taht fi erus t’nsaw luaP
snoitseuq esoht deksa I fi nevE
ll’rehtegot sevlow lla er’ew yad eht
.meht ees ot nevig evah dluow aksarbeN ni oga syad eerht neeb d’eh flow eht hcum woh rettam on
.ereht saw flow regnuoy eht nettogrof d’eh fi sa ,deltrats rekcurt ehT .elttil a
”?wonk uoy ,eromyna namuh yltcaxe t’nia uoy snaem gniht taht fi ,gniht a revo etanimur ot dnet uoY
,rehtie ,emit eht lla tcefrep leef t’nod em ot tcefrep kool ohw esoht teb d’I ,neht tuB
siht od ot tnaw llits uoY
.eveileb t’ndid luaP hcihw ,sregnif sa suortxed sa t’nerew swalc dias d’ehs esuaceb detfihs ton ereh eno ylno eht
.yppah er’yeht taht yppah tsuj m’I taht naht rehto dna
,erutinruf elbatrofmoc dna dlo
,regnirratS ,inohaS
.sgniht yzarc od ot nilliw erom tol a ylneddus s’eh neht
.esnecil dna kcurt ym dah llits I tub
,cidem eht yawa evaw ot deirt seliM
,yaw eht fo tuo erew ),naD(
”.taht ekil eno tcepxe t’ndid I ,uoy rof kcap eht ni ecalp a saw ereht uoy dlot I nehw“
tuoba klat ot detnaw t’nevah yeht dna“
ekomsdoow dna esnecni saw htaenrednu tub ,flow fo sraey dna sraey dna
.degnoleb eh erehw kcap a dnif ot
.savnac sulprus ymra eht no ssorc der eht revo ’cinilc tev‘
”?MEHT…fo eno yreve
airohpsyd rof tuo-kconk tih eno a eb d’ti demussA .nug eht depmuj …I
.denrut d’eh woh oravlA deksa d’eh
”,naem uoy ecalp adnik eht tuoba onnud I“ .dehgis luaP
.tnet a ni gnittis erew yehT
.htaenrednu gnihtemos ta dellup dna trihs sih denottubnu ,nwod dehcnuh eH
ruoy si taht od ll’gniht ylnO
”.tcurtsnoc laicos a si ’flow‘ dna ’namuh‘ neewteb yranib eht“
,floWcaM boR yb
,elbitrevnoc a fo edis eht revo gninael saw
,sgniht denigami ev’I“
”.htiw trats ot hguone esolc ,tahw wonk uoy...“
,seye sih ni htped drah a saw erehT
.gnihtemos ro era seittop atrop eht erehw ksa ro ,pup tsol a dnif ot deen
”.meht ot riaf mees t'nseod taht
...“ ”?nam a eb ot pu worg tub lrig a nrob er’uoy“
.meht fo owt eht ylno saw kcaP taerG eht
”?sretfihsepahs su llac yehT“ ”.wonk uoy ,snamuH“
”,dik ,noitseuq yvaeh a s’tahT“
.meht ksa ot evaH ?wonk I
strihs FFATS ni sevlow rehto evif ro ruoF
,yellav eht ni koot taht yaw a ni ,yltnesba
,dias flow ydnas eht
”?ecalp a tog ev’uoy fi wonk t’nod uoy“
”.eno rehto yreve htiw gnipeels s’meht fo eno yrevE
”.gnihtemos ro ,repap loohcs eht rof tcejorp adnik emos niod s’diK“ ”?ereh no niog s’tahw
”,tcefrep kool ti ekam ohw sevlow tem ev’I
.citatsce erom eht
.sih ta deggut oravlA
”!uaeruB eht morf mih devas ahplA ruoy dnA“ ”.ecaep eb d’ereht
.mih ta deknilb flow rehto ehT
:ti fo llup eht leef t’ndid eh dias eh fi gniyl neeb evah dluow eH
.drow eht gnidaerps detrats ,llew
s’taht ezilaer uoY“
.sevitcepsrep rieht rof sevlowerew rehto ksa ot
deltrats eht ecnO .ylmrif yrev tub
.tfihs yeht nehw kool ot detnaw syawla yeht woh yltcaxe kool ot teg ohw“
cisum eht ni ecalp eht otni pets ot dlrow eht ni gniht tseisae eht eb dluow ti tub—
.drawkwa laer eb annog s’taht tseb ta neht
.desiurb neve ylerab m’I“
’?kcap‘ yas tsuj ton yhw—
seinomrah rieht wonk tey ton thgim eH .revo dna revo
,emag eht evol I dna ,reyalp a si esle enoyrevE
”?sralloc eht htiw od ot evah taht seod tahw tuB“
.emit fo tol ,yenom fo tol a
”.me dnif uoy ecnO
”.htaerb ym gnidloh ton m’I tub ,ti yrt nac
”.esruc a s’ti kniht elpoep rewef sekaM
,ssel ti deen I ,lleW“
.thguoht ni denworf luaP ”.rednib a  tog I“
flowffats eht dewollof dah luaP
,ksa dluoc luaP erofeb ,deunitnoc oravlA ”,thgirla m’I“ ”.msicroxe deirt neve yehT .enabsflow htiw
’,namtihW .C‘ dias taht—
”?tfihs ton ot reisae ti sekam taht gniht a ,ekil ,taht sI“
.ylekil erom taht sekam od I tahw epoh I dna
.yrots siht wonk ydaerla ot uoy detcepxe yeht ekil tlef taht yaw a ni eugav erew sciryl eht tub
,teews ylgnisirprus saw aet ehT
detniap yarps dah ydobemoS
.msimitpo eudnu spahrep htiw
,truh fo dnik taht hguorht gniog tuohtiw ereh tog—
.noitisoporp tnereffid a saw ti gniod tub
.uoy laer eht hctam
.dnim s’luaP ni pu dezalb
.taerg era syad emoS .drah os dnuos ti ekam ot naem t’nod I“
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht morf seigolohtna ni
”,meht ot snaem flowerew a gnieb tahw elpoep tnereffid gniksa eb ot desoppus …m’I“
.meht nioj ot mih gnirad
”.punip ekacfeeb yrruf a
.hguoht ,yademos ebyaM“ .gnihton dias eH
,reh nioj ot noinapmoc reh rof ecaps tfel tub ,etinarg mraw eht no tops gninnus eht nekat dah flow ydnas eht
taht“ ,elkcit t’ndid wohemos taht yaw a ni daeherof s’luaP dehcuot sreksihw sih
.nwo ym no gnilevarT .tol a
”,naem I“ ’.etilop ton‘
,ydob ruoy ekam ot
.gnos eht tsuj naht erom ot noitativni na saw ti ylbissop dna
,t’nseod noisufsnart doolb a tub ti od etib a ro xes seod yhw ,sevlow otni nrut su sekam tahw—
.ocixeM weN hguorht etuor a gnivird saw I“
”-retsim ,ti tuoba klat ot tnaw t’nod uoy fI“
.esoht tuohtiw ti htiw yawa nettog evah t’ndluoc eh ,haey taht degdelwonkca luaP
,rehtona eno htiw devlovni yllacitnamor lla era ohw
,ti htiw od ot gnihtyna dah doG eveileb I kniht t’nod I“
saw ’em‘ gnos eht ni elpoep eht fo eno revehcihw—
.rehtie emit taht niw t’ndid dna erofeb tnemugra siht dah ev’uoy nehw od uoy yaw eht
,elpmis ylevitpeced saw gnos ehT
”?krow taht ekil ti gniyas seoD
”!wonk neve t’nod I ,naM“ ”?ton er’uoy dnA“ ”.yag
.noitangidni emos htiw delbmum luaP
,gnidnatsrednu etelpmocni yltnerappa s’luaP revo delworg eh ”,dnoceS“
.etam a evah I ...woN
…denrael I gnihtyreve tuB
od ot woh uoy wohs ll’ti epoh I
,sdeb dna smra rieht ni emoclew a dnuof
,snoitseuq ydobon taht
.dednetni syad gnimoc eht tahw ssel erac t’ndluoc luaP ,thginoT
kaeps ot gniyrt luaP deciton meht fo enon taht ssenisub nwo rieht no tnetni os erew—
tuoba ton s’ti“ ,dehgis eh
taht si gninigami yllaer peek I tahW“
yeht …llew ,reve smelborp lla evlos annog s’flow a tsuj sa gnivil enoyreve kniht yeht fI
,sworbeye reh desiar ehs
”,em“ edam eltsihw eht erehw strap eht rof tpecxe
.htuom sih hguorht tuo ,eson sih hguorht ni dehtaerb eh ”…kO“
detfihs ehs tniop eht enilrednu ot tsuj ”,ereH“
,reliart eht em tog I“
,eb ot mih detcepxe yeht ohw eb dluoc eh fi
,mih dniheb dezalb tesnus ehT .nepo ti gnidloh
.ti enod ev’yeht gnizilaer neve tuohtiW .lliw ti
”,kcap eno evah d’I ebyaM“
,ees uoy tnemaciderp tneserp ruoy ot evitaler ,tniop ehT“
,dnah a devaw flow gnuoy ehT
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.ti rof deen eht leef t’nod tsuJ
”.tahw s’tahw mih llet d’ew dna snoitseuq ksa dluoc eh mih dlot I“
,deksa d’eh ,s’seliM ekil noitatuper a htiw kcap a nioj ot ecnahc a dah flow a fI
.ti dnif ot tcepxe t’ndiD
hguoht ,neewteb levart I skcap tnereffid ni
thgil a suoreneg sa ni
”’,fles eurt‘ ruoy gnieb flow eht tuoba klat lliw su fo tol a… !si tniop ehT“
…snaem ti osla tuB
”.sevlesmeht nettib neeb ev’t’ndluow ,em tib reveohw ebyam ,dlrow tcefrep a nI .erus ,rednow I“
.kcurt eht otni kcab
,dnA“ .detcejbo seliM
.ngis on saw ereht
,tol a snoitseuq eseht htiw laed ot evah I .yllaer ,uoy ta dam ton m’I ,dik ,kooL“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
”!ahplA na ton m’I“
.thguoht eh ,aet fo dnik emoS
.noitatuper a dah kcap eht taht nwonk t’ndah luaP
si gniksa eb dluohs uoy noitseuq eht ebyaM
.ypareht topkcarC
:ekil gnihtemos em llet yeht drawretfa
”.mih noitnem sevlow elpuoc a draeh I
,tcejbus eht egnahc oT
,yks tesnus-tsop til-esiouqrut eht tsniaga sllih fo enil eht dennacs seye ,kcab decnalg luaP ”,erehw ,hU“
dna ’etilop‘ fo yranib eht otni yltaen tif t’ndah ti tcepsus ot luaP del
,meht deksa uoy fi regaw d’I“
,hu ,tuoba denialpxe uoy llit ecnereffid yna saw ereht em ot rucco t’ndid tI
tnemelffab ni daeh sih detlit luaP retfa dnoces tilps A
.yks eht otni pu derats ,mih deksa luaP nehw
,slrig eht htiw tis ymA dna newG
”?tfihs uoy nehw elam yaw eht lla nrut t’nod uoy naem uoy oD“
,uoy rof ekam ot ecaps tahw ees nac kcap eht nehw dna
.skaerb moorhtab yna ref pu ekam ot
yerg ot eulb morf dehcaelb-nus—trihs pu-nottub a dna ,enodnu sparts eht htiw ,sllarevo gniraew saw flow dlo ehT ”.dik ,onnud I“
.eeD ro ,craM ,ekaJ ylekil ,meht fo eno dias
,nac eh erofeb tuB
yeht fi ot og nac yeht enoemos er’uoy llet ot enoyreve rof yaw a s’ti dnA
,resolc eht saw cisum eht
,dnefed ro etaitogen ot evah t’nod I ecalp a
,dworc eht hguorht rehtohcae gnisahc stnecseloda tnarebuxe ,srenol dlo delzzirg
.selcnu sih erew yeht thguoht tsuj d’eH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,ekil ,fo esuac lla tub
.fo erac nekat neeb ydaerla d’eh
yletelpmoc reven er’uoy
.og d’I esle erehw aedi oN
,elihw eht lla ylevitnetta snoitseuq s’luaP gnirewsna neeb d’ehs tub
.ti od ot erac t’nod
,tekcaj denoihsaf dlo na dna snaej
,rehtona ro noitanibmoc eno ni rehtegot lla er’yehT
…ot denrut yeht ,netsil t’ndluow yeht nehW
.delkcuhc flow dlo eht
.tnaw yllaer uoy tahw rof gnikool luferac eb attog uoy sseug …haeY“
tcurtsnoc laicos eht thguoht I“
”.troper loohcs ruoy ni nwod tup uoy drow eht ’s’flowfiW‘ fi“
.taht sa ydit sa ton s’tI“
”.htiw emac I kcap eht ekil
.tsixe t’nod yeht ,tnereffid enog d’ti fi eb d’I ,snamuh eht ro ,sevlow ehT
2 trap( floWcaM boR yb
ev’uoy em llet esaelP“
,ylregae deddon luaP ”,haey ,hO“
.no derekcilf sthgil fo sgnirts eht dna
”,aedi taht dekil su fo tol a ,llew
”,noitatressid eht piks ot ,haeY“
.ralloc dna trihs ’FFATS‘ a ni flow rehtona ot devaw oravlA
.daeh sih koohs luaP
lanif a htiw dnA
,deb s’esle enoyreve fo tuo na ni rehtohcae gnisahc syawla s’enoyreve dna rehtegot sevil enoyreve erehw dnik eht naem uoy fi tuB
.tnacifingis eb ot tnaem neeb dah ti ekil dednuos tahT ”.efil nwo
,setalP sA giB sA seyE deman kcurt doof a dniheb flow eht denialpxe ”,si gniht ehT“
.waj sih tes luaP ”?sruoy fo nalp
.meht neewteb tfihs uoY“
,htiw ereh emac eh eno eht gninioj tuoba erusnU
,elucylop gib eno er’yeht si“
namow redlo na gnicaf flesmih dnuof luaP ,denrut eh nehw
.meht tsuj saw ti nehT
,detatiseh luaP ”,on dna seY“
edis namuh a tog ev’uoy fI
.taht ekil sdrow otni ti tup ot elba neeb t’ndah eh taht suoivne yldlim
”.deb ni od nac uoy gnihtyna naht dnob resolc a s’sklof htiw gnignis“
elohw siht htiw ma I elbatrofmoc woh“
.thgis fo tuo erew yeht erofeb
”.nwonk eb ot thguo tI
.yks thgindim eht fo tuo tuc neeb dah epahs sih ekil kool
.eip-dnah deirf fo dnik emos ebyam ro
ekam seod gnitfihS
dezilaer luaP erofeb
,shtoob eht ,setispmac eht
ynapmoc tnelis luaP tpek dna ,slaoc gnirebmuls eht revo elttek pmac lemane na tes flow krad ehT
daerht eht otni evol dna efil sih detaitnatsbusnart
.VR eht morf degreme ro shtoob eht morf
”!tahw uoy llet I ,pu tes ecalp siht teg ot kniht d’uoy naht niluah ograc erom tol a koot tI
”,ma’am yrros ,on ,hU“
,kcurtsewa elttil a naht erom hguoht ylevarg
.ti droffa t’nac su fo toL .gnihtyreve dna seiregrus dna senicideM
,htob fo emos eb syawla tub pleh t’nac uoy ,edis flow a dna
,slaoc gniyerg eht revo segasuas eht denrut eH
?ris ,htrow s’ti tahw roF“
.sebuc ,neve ,llams otni steeb dna ,selppa ,seotatop fo elip a gnitrevnoc ylisub erew dna
,ytiradilos ciporhtnacyl fo satsiv erom yna tif t’ndluoc eh
”…tub ,yaw emas eht yltcaxe krow t’nseod ti ebyaM
,og meht tel dah dna ,thgirla erew yeht decnivnoc yllanif saw cidem eht retfa ,seliM dias
.swap s’luaP morf gab eht dekculp htiw ereh emoc d’eh flow ehT
d’yeht ”,rettam t’nod snoitseuq eht sseug I“
:erucsbo erew eno siht no sesrev ehT
,gniggaw pots t’ndluow liat s’luaP ”,tuB
.nus gnittes eht sa roloc emas eht tsomla ,enohs seye sih
.yllatnemirepxe sih deffins luaP
.oot eno s’taht ,haey lleW“
”.sruoy t’nsi ti dna
.rehcaetloohcs a ekil kool reh edam taht yaw a ni luaP drawot denael
”?flowerew a t’nerew uoy dias uoy nehw tnaem ti tahw tuoba desufnoc m’I yltsom ,hU“
.egnulp eht erofeb revid a ekil htaerb a koot
esuac ,ees uoy ,esruc a saw ti thguoht lla eW
,dik ,did I deednI“ .luaP deksa
senob nekorb rof kcehc reh tel ylgnigdurgeb seliM
”.daD ro moM tub ydobyna tem I erar ytterp saw ti pirt siht erofeB“
”,netsiL“ ”.god ot pu sddA
”uoY roF kcaP taerG eht ni ecalP a s'erehT“   yojne esaelP
,denrecnoc m’I sa raf sa
syad gnimoc eht fi dnA
,sevlowerew dnuora pu werg I .gnihtyreve
,demrifnoc luaP ,meht evoba sllihtoof ehT
”?’eninimef‘ dna ’enilucsam‘ neewteb saw“
”?ahctnia ,pup luftcepseR“ ”?ris ,evil uoy od“
,ecnalg delffab s’luaP ot deilper seliM
,luaP gnicarbme nrut sih koot nitraM sa ,naD dias
.nub a otni hcae meht dils dna
.etarobale t’ndid dna ,dias eh ”,nettib saw I“
’retpahC namuhartxE sretsmaeT‘ dias taht pac gnikool-wen a dah eH
”!gninialpxe rof uoy knaht ,uoy gniteem ecin
.enif s’ti ,oN“ .nageb luaP
”.rehto eht erom semitemos
.yhtapme tsniaga kaeps ot em morf ti eb raf dna
.yad eht ni kcab ,oot taht ekil snoisulcnoc fo tol a ot depmuj I ,ekil tub
.tsael ta wonk sevlow sklof ro
ton er’uoy ,tsrif ,kO“
stekcop tog ev’uoy fi rettam on uoy htiw gat eman dna DI ruoy evah ot yaw a s’tI“
.era yeht ohw tsuj
,dluow yeht dlrow tcefrep a ni fi neve
.ot gniog syawla saw I kniht I ,lleh
.trihs lennalf yggab a rednu ,detfihsnu
,flow eht htiw pu dekcip I gnihtemos s’taht ebyam ,onnud I
t’ndid yeht yas d’yeht
,hcuot ni teg d’eh desimorp luaP
.yag lla er’yeht tuB“
,tsruwtarb fo etib a nekat dna riahcnwal sih ni kcab denael dah flow dlo yggahs eht
”,ereht trats ,thgirlA“
,flow gib eht rof kool detnioppasid a htiw
dah oravlA dnik emas eht—
”,rednow reve t’nod uoY“
.htolchceerb a ekil tsiaw sih dnuora seveels sti yb deit—
,draob gnittuc dna lwob rieht htiw
”,su fo emos taht mret eht gnisu t’nera sevlow elamef
,hu ,-op yrruf ekil dekool taht gnihtemos otni tfihs d’I dna
.tcefrep t’nsi ti si ytilaer ehT“
,knupariM ,enrohtwaH .S.J
.seert detnuts dna setispmac gnoma doots dna sdnuorg niam elohw eht dessorc
.rehtohcae taert snamuh sa yldab sa rehtohcae taert sevlow nees reven ev’I tub
.daor eht no emit sih lla sdneps tahw wonk I flow ylno
elzzum eht fo edis eht no kcil tfiws a
,em rof ecalp a sah kcap hcihw wonk I esuaC
tsuj naD dna seliM ekil syug od lleh eht woH“
,noitcerid rehto eht ni dnA“
.ylerecnis deddon cidem eht ”,sevlow ffats eht llA“
,enodnu eb reven llahs taht noitaitnatsbusnart a dnA
,ohw flow a saw ereht ,oga sraey wef a“
”?tnereffid neeb evah dluoc ti fi“
,gnidnatsrednusim eht tcerroc ot ton
.teef reh ot reh depleh eno ydnas eht sa dehgis flow nud eht ”?nos ,morf semoc ’flowerew‘ drow eht erehw wonk uoy oD“
.maerts eht rof dedaeh dna
,sa yfitnedi sevlesmeht t’nod yeht gnihtemos elpoep gnillac dnuora og uoy fI“
tem saw noitseuq taht hcihw htiw noisserpxe ehT
”!gniht siht gnizinagro erew ew
.rehtona pu worg dna gniht eno nrob
,sevlowerew fo gnirehtag ediwnoitan tsrif eht ,kcaP taerG ehT ot deyenruoj luaP ,emit tsaL
:sllems sa ylno detsixe taht moor eht otni repeed yltneg mih llup
”!nokcer I ,niod sdeen tahw enod teg ot hguone s’taht dna ,enim s’ti skniht tnimbug eht tuB .dnal enohsohS nretsaE ro enneyehC rehtie s’ereh siht“
,hguone enod meht degduj
.sag raet fo revoc rednu nur dna tuc d’yeht dna
.did eh nehw desirprus yleniuneg saw eh taht eno teg ot gnipoh t’nsaw eh dneterp ot gniyrt ysub os neeb dah ohw
.tuo dial yltaen neeb dah seitissecen eht lla erehw
”.era uoy ohw sseug dnoces ot nivah reven ,ecin neeb ev’tsuM“
sekat ti teb I dna
.trihsrednu na eb ot thguoht luaP taht gnihtemos revo dednah eH
”?ti t’ndluow ,ediced ot meht rof eb d’taht ,lleW“
.sgatgod reh deregnif cidem eht
,era uoy ohw uoy llet annog t’nia yhtapme tuB
”.ecalp a gnivah si
…ot gnineppah saw tahw ebyam ,thgisdnih ni
,sniarb sih dekcarw luaP ”…taht si ,hO“
,lennalf ni flow eht evag eH
erew yeht dlot tog
”?ereh gniht elohw siht evah meht tel ohw flow eht ot olleh yas ot thguo ew fi tuoba gniklat erew ew rebmemeR ?tahw sseuG“
”,retsinac sag a tsuj saw tI“  )2 fo
,sevlow rehto ot klat ot mih llet ot naD rof gniht eno saw tI
,laer rof kcap a ni ecalp
,denrut dah dlrow eht ni snamuh lla nehw yad eno taht dna ,kcaP taerG eht ot elpoep llac ot mih dlot dah doG dias eH
”reverof aiulellaH“ yltsoM
’saiulellah‘ eht ,gnignis naht rehtar ,gnilwoh erew meht fo emos yaw eht ro—
,lwob a otni seotatop debuc eht fo tsal eht tpews yeht ”,wonk t’nod I oS“
,lavirra no nees d’eh nibac eht fO .ytpme erew
elgnis a otni rehtegot skcap wes ot hcihw htiw
.kcab dellac yeht nehw meht ot klat ot desoppus saw seliM dna
”?yob a ylterces erew tub lrig a ekil gnikool nrob er’uoy nehw s’ti oS“
.srats eht rednu peels ,tae ot tnuH .gnilevart pots reveN
.ti htaeneb dnuof eb ot flow fo yteirav yreve dna
”.msihpromid lauxes ssel tol a tog ev’sevlow taht tsuj s’ti kniht I dna t’nod I syad emoS
erac ot mees t’nod I edis siht no tuB
,tekcaj rehtael nworb a ni
”!kcaP taerG eht niyojne neeb ay epoH !ahcteem’t dooG“
.detcepxe d’ehs noitcaer eht yltcaxe saw siht dezilaer eh
.erifpmac rieht ot denruter luaP nehw dias naD
,oravlA dias ”,tub ,yug siht tuoba yleritne ton s’ti ,lleW“
norpa der a rednu
tuo detniop luaP retfa
”.noitadnuof dilos a no s’kcap ym snaeM
”.flow elam rehto yna sa emas eht hcum ytterp llems uoy dnA ?llems
,derepsihw flow rehto eht ”,esimorp t’nac I“
.tnatropmi s’ti ,kcaP taerG eht htiw gniod er’ew krow ehT
.deunitnoc flow krad eht
”!emit eht lla detfihs yats t’nac uoy“
a evah ot ,flowerew laer a eb ot ekil saw ti tahw tuo dnif ot detnaw I
…ot deklat I enoyreve
,teksab a ni sehtolc fo elip a pota ti deppals flow tsrif ehT
,elprup fo edahs emos dekool tsomla ti taht kcalb krad os ruf dna
.taht ekil kcap a ni m’I
esoht fo eno eb ot looc eb d’ti“
,evoba tesnus fo stnanmer tsal eht
flowerew a nidnif otni em deklat relwoH lepsoG eht woh si hcihW
.tey yawa ruoh na saw esirnus hguoht neve thgil worg noziroh tsae eht gnihctaw saw eh ekil
”!won erac ekat llaY
,su htiw kcab gnimoc er’uoy naem taht seoD“ deksa naD
.hguorht tnew I tahw fo esuac ma I flow eht m’I
,yggab ssel yltnacifingis won hguoht niaga denottub ylitsah
.tnemesab eht ni egac eht htiw gniht elohw eht diD
mutnemom hcum oot rehtag yeht tsel
,ynohpmys eht gnidne rotcudnoc a ekil smra sih daerps flow eht
,dnoyeb tserof eht
.srewsna yna uoy evig ll’siht
,yldeggod daeha degrof oravlA
,sllaw elbisivni tsniaga sevlesmeht ecarb ot fi sa sdnah rieht desiar yeht
,noitpo na saw yporhtnacyl tuo dnuof I nehW
ereh thgir emeht siht no
”.oga gnol kcart peek ot gniyrt pu evag I
.enif tsuj srats eht rednu peels nac ro
”.ksa ot ecnahc a tog reven I .em tib reveohw
.siht ekil ti ta kooL“
,delttes gnineve eht sa
enoemos dessap retal luaP nehw tuB
,nur llahs ytinamuh hguorht noitamrofsnart hsiflow a nehT
”?erofeb nosrep snart a fo draeh
.elba saw eh sa ytitnedi +QTBGL fo stecaf ynam sa edulcni ot
,deraeppasid yehT
.si esle enoyreve ohw tsuj
.mih degaruocne ereht regnol on saw taht nibac a ni ssik a fo yromem eht tub
taht tahw si ,snamuh elamef dna snamuh elam naht tnereffid yllacisyhp
…saw I demussa ,erofeb ,allef a deredisnoc reven a t’ndluoW .daor eht no wonk I sevlow wef a htiw moor letom a derahs ev’I timda ll’I
’?fo trap eb annaw uoy dluow kcap adnik
.detnaw eh noitseuq eht ksa ot woh rebmemer t’ndluoc luaP ”…uoy era ,tiaW“
mih fo flah rehto ehT
ll’taht skcap ,spots raluger evah ebyaM
.derepmihw flow gnuoy eht
.elihw a ti tuoba thguoht ylbaborp ev’su ev’tsom sseug I tuB“
.ffo wap sih seirrow eh erofeb thgir lla er’ew wonk naD tel dna kcab teg dluohs I“
,erifpmac eht revo sreweks no gnitiaw tsruwtarb rehto eht fo llems eht erongi ot delggurts luaP
”,nosrep a“ naem tsuj ot
.etamkcap s’seliM yleritne t’nsaw eh desirprus yltsenoh saw oravlA
”?thgir ,ereht ni sthguoht namuh dah llits uoY
.tuoba klat sevlow emos raeh uoy ekil ,ksam a s’namuh eht dna fles laer ym si flow eht taht yub I fi onnud I woN“
tahw‘ ,noitseuq eht ekam“
,kcaP taerG eht fo yteritne eht revo dekool evah dluoc eh ereh morF
.ti tuoba deklat reve enoyna yaw ylno eht s’taht
.regral elttil a ton fi ,noinapmoc sih sa egral sa tsuj saw eh ,pu emac eh nehW
,edisa htob tes ,gum ytpme s’luaP detcelloc flow krad eht ”,lleW“
”.godpeehs a yllautca t’nsaw I llet t’ndluoc yeht esuac ladem a now ecno I .raf ytterP“
,redluohs reh no elddif eht gninut no desucof yltnetni saw ruf etihw-ylraen eht htiw flow eht
”.elihw a rof enog erew uoY“
,eno erom er’uoy semitemoS
”.sih fo snaf gib ytterp era ffats eht atser eht attoL“
,era yeht revetahw ,si ti reveohw
.dessim tsuj d’eh hcihw
,saw taht erehw wonk t’ndid ehs hcihw ’,htoob eht ta‘
,nosmirc suonimul dna diviv a gum s’flow krad eht morf semulp gnimaets eht nrut ot elgna thgir eht ta tsuj saw ,tnemom a rof ,tesnus eht ”,ecneirepxe ym nI“
!hguone llew em seod ehs
,nam a enigami ro ,ydal a enigami
.seye sih revo wol dellup
railimaf saw enut eht tub
,puorg sih dessag raet
eucebrab ytsur llams a htiw deppiuqe saw hcrop nibac ehT
.deggurhs eH ”.snaem
,dnuora nworht neeb dah
,luaP ta gnikool regnol on saw eh
,dik ,si gniht dnA
”,ti fo tnecs eht tog ev’uoy kniht I“
spahrep selat esohw esoht fo ecnaifed ni eman nwo sih ni sgat htiw ralloc a gniraeb
.rehtruf neve nwod dehcnuh ,gnitfihs saw eh nehT
.yllacitahpme torrac a deppohc yehT
.dias namtihW ”.t’nia sevlow attoL“ ”.desserpmi
”.nwod ti nur ot sekat ti tahw od nac uoy fi wonk t’nod tsuj uoY“
,deffuh flow krad eht
,melborp a saw taht yhw ees ehs did ron
,eson sih fo egdirb eht dehctarcs flow deroloc-thgindim eht
…evah I eveileb t’nod I ,risson ,hU“
”,snoitseuq emos gniksa tsuj ,haeY“
,tniop siht ta ,reisae saw ti dnA
,raf ton dna llems yb dnif ot ysae saw ylikcul tub
.ti od ot esle ydobon dna pu denaelc eb ot dedeen taht ssem a saw ereht dezilaer tsuj d’eh ekil erom tol a dna yrgna ssel tol a dekool flow dalc-lennalf ehT
’sessa rieht attuo thgir seloh eht eus‘ sdrow ehT
”.si siht revetahw
”!nam ,tnaw uoy fi ,ni nioj ot emoclew eb d’uoY“
.ot deen I nehw god yarts a sa ssaP
.sevlow eseht lla rof ydaer ecalp a dah kcap eht taht ton s’ti“
,eno sah ot deklat I flow yrevE“ .deddon luaP
.sepoh hgih htiw ereh emac …I“
,kcap eht ERA sevlow eseht lla taht s’tI
,esarhper ylitsah ot tnemom a koot
,ruf bard-etoyoc ,flow yggahs ,dlo nA ”!ynnos ,ereht yeH“
”?namuh a tsuj nevE ?erofeb nosrep snart a tem reven“
.srettam tahw s’taht dna
,ssenkrad eht ot tsujda ot tnemom a seye sih koot tI
”…si nrop tahw wonk I“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.gniht kcaP giB enO
.deksa seliM ”?puP ,ko uoY“
.rehtona eno otni nur ew nehw rehtegot laem a teg
,neM mayloP yaG siC yllacificeps tneserper ot desu dah eh ylsuoiverp hcihw
.mih dniheb eciov a dias ”?pup ,tsol uoy erA“
noom lluf eht yhw
.seidemer kloF .sdohtem rehto
tnemeganaM ecalupoP namuhartxE fo uaeruB eht fo stnega
”?siht ekil syawla tsuj erew uoY
.oot ,tuo ti erugif ot dah yehT ’.wonk tsuj‘
.M.P.E fo .B eht ni dellac yehT
.elpoep llet …ot deen I“
.rohtua eht yb daeR
.detnemmoc flow krad eht
,derrefnoc dah sralloc deggat-DI dna
,ecarbme s’flow krad eht yb detaitini neeb d’eh erehw
”.em etib ot mih niksa dna
,ti tnaem neve dna dootsrednu eh dias
nibac taht rof gnidaeh erew yeht
”.ees ot redrah tol a tsuj saw ti ,era uoy tahw erew syawla uoY
.meht dnif nac I reverehw ,sevloW
ssom dna seert dna niar htaenrednu repeed llits dna
.tfihs ot deen uoy raf woh rettam oN .sehtolc ro
,nogaw noitats gnikool-elbisnes a fo kcab eht ni gab eht tes flow ydnas eht ”!yllaedI“
,esoht tuoba yrrow ot emit eht tsap gnol saw ti tub noitseuq edur a eb dluow siht deirrow luaP ”,uoy oD“
,esruoc’a ,denrut nitteg rof em detserra spoc nehw em deppord ynapmoC
”,tfihs t’nac I nehw rof ,oS“
,detfihs ,flow egral A
”.nialpxe ll’I dna em rof pmac ot kcab ffuts siht yrrac tuob woh“
?ti ta pmuj ton yhw
”.sseug I ,ksa ot efas yllanif s’ti yad eht eb
.deraefa oot eb ot desu tsuj I ebyam ro
.sraey rof t’nevah ,rettam taht rof ,ydobyna htiW
’.fyw‘ saw namow a rof drow eht dna
,siht ekil enif tsuj em ekil yeht ,etam yM“
,drah ton ,naD dessik dna
”!puP ,era uoy ereht ,hO“
,spup htiw stnerap—meht fo llA
,rohpatem flowerew eht dnapxe ot saw noitnetni s’rohtua eht ,siht gnitirw nI
.tibah fo ecrof yb tsuj ynomrah otni gnippils neve erew meht fo emoS
”?htiw emac uoy kcap eht ot kcab gnitteg dnah a deen uoY“
…rehto fi ,nuh ,ssenisub ruoy ton s’tI
,yhtapme ni esicrexe na flesruoy gnivah neeb ev’uoy sdnuos ti ,woN
.taht morf semoc ’flowerew‘ drow eht“
.rednow tub pleh t’ndluoc osla eh
”…dnatsrednu I kniht t’nod I“
.nwo sih morf sdnuorgpmac fo retsulc etisoppo eht sdrawot
.rehto eht ro eno
”.pup ,tsol kool uoY“  .derit yrev
,eludehcs a fo hctiB
”!mih devas ohw seno eht er’uoY ?relwoH lepsoG eht wonk ton uoy oD“
”?taht ni uoy rof ecalp a ees t’nod uoy dna
”’?eb ot tnaw uoy od ohw‘
.srehto naht retteb s’ti ekil leef I syad emoS
,snamuh neve ebyaM
.tuo delur eb t’ndluoc eeD spahrep hguoht ,ymA ro newG ylekil ,rehtona dedda
.em eruc ot deirt ylimaf yM“
”.su fo eno er’uoy
.desserpmi saw eh kniht t’nod I .ti tuoba klat ot tnaw t’ndid eH“ .denworf luaP
etteuohlis sih edam dna
”?wonk uoy ,lacitcarp s’ti ,lleW“
ruf yerg ydnas ot
,llufyalp ,hsiyppup dna trela ,mih no erew seye s’flow yreve won dna
,snoitnetni tseb eht htiw neve
”?kcaP taerG eht tuoba erom emos raeh ot tnaw reve uoy fi …dnA
seirots suoiverp dnif nac uoy dna
,tsiniloiv eht dna luaP neewteb tcatnoc eye dnoces tilps eht ssorca dehsalf noitativni eht fo noitaretier sseldrow A
,uoy ees elpoep yaw eht dna ,tsixe uoy ekil leef uoy yaw eht
”?ti teg ,tuo tsehc eht nettalf ot
retaw mraw htiw seye sih desnir dah cidem eht dna—
”?tfihs uoy nac raf woH
,sgnirts ot wob tes ehs ”,yawynA“
,dnatsdnab eht ,sgalf eht ,skcurt doof eht
”,htiw emac uoy kcap eht gninioj melborp eht oS“
elihw elttil a rof dna
.kniht mih depleh yltnerappa hcihw
”…t’nod I …t’nseod taht
,noitnetta gniyap neeb ,tcaf ni ,dah luaP ”,yranib
”,ereht ,tib a esraeher attog eW“
,dehgis eno rellams ehT
’,yaw eht lla gninrut‘
,gnoleb ot desoppus saw eh ecalp eht ta ecnahc sih neeb dah
tuons rednels ,liat fo tfut gnol ,ruf deroloc-reppoc yffulf—
”.esrepsid ot gniyrt m’I taht woN ?seidal …hu
,flow eht delbmurg
rehtegot lla erew dna
”’.kcap a fo trap‘ si tog I lla diarfa m’I“
si sihT“ .deknilb luaP
,ti gniraeh dnim t’nod uoy fi ,lleW“
.nitraM dna seliM neewteb edis rehto eht no tas
”.tsrif ta ,esruc a saw ti thguoht I“  .erolpxe ot
”?sretfihsepahs su sllac ohW“
,serauqS egroeG ,regguR .P .B
.lamron erew yeht thguoht I ekil ,gniyrt erew yeht seruc eht fo emos denoitnem I nehw ereht fo tuo em tog rekrowesaC .won doog m’I“
,feihcrekcen dedaf a ,strohs omac ni
”.erom yna tif t’nseod tsuj ti ,flow a sa reggib hcum nmad os teg tsuj I taht yltsom s’ti tub
,syenruoj nwo sih no—pihsredael ot noissecorp larenuf morf seliM enruob ecno dah taht—elcycrotom nwod-em-dnah eht edor
snaem yllaretiL
.daeh sih koohs luaP nehw deunitnoc ehs
,kcurt eht morf dellems eb ot llits secart eht yb gnigduJ
’nam‘ drow eht desu yehT
draob gnittuc a pu tes ot
dik a sa mih llac ot desu I tahw tsuj s’taht ,elcnu yllaer ton ,llew—
yaw eht fo tsom flow krad eht dewollof d’eH
.seye sih dellor eH
”?trats eht morf ,wonk
,keehc eht no mih hcuot
?thgir ,rehtegot emoc ot snamuh dna sevlow tnaw ew
.esruoc fo ikahK dna ,gnoS aynoT
”,tsol adnik taht toN .risson ,hO“
,wob eht htiw derutseg ehs ”,thguac llew
,snilloC troF atni nwod reh evird I ,semoc retniW
”?kcap ruo nioj ot
.yadot ytud hsart nO
fo gab a uoy ewo I“
.etispmac txen eht rof dedaeh dna ,dias eh
,noom lluf eht dedaerd I .lufniap yreV
,rossecederp a htiw mih detalfnoc
,rehtohcae ref tuo kool ,hcuot ni yats eW
”?thgir ,kcap a gninioj er’uoy nehw tuoba erac uoy gnihtemos yllausu ton
.dnuora lla kcaP taerG
desivda neeb s’eh
,kcar eht no gnuh taoc
”.eergasid ot edur smees
”?rehtohcae htiw ecaep ni evil ,etarepooc oT
.rohtua eht yb daer ,floWcaM boR yb
denialpxe ’elucylop‘ drow eht dedeen luaP
,sevlow ref ograc luah I woN
”?…uoy erA ?uoy …lla siht sI“
”.mih tem kcap sih tub—
.stnuoc taht ebyaM
.taht tuoba erus t’nsaw luaP
.stluser eht htiw eugra t’nac I …em rof tuB“
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT
”.su llac dluohs srehto tahw ediced ot su fo hcae rof s’tI
,taht esimorp od I tuB
?taht gniyas reve mom rebmemer t’nac …I“
,dethgil erew serifpmac eht
”.eulb eht fo tuo pu nrut I fi em ezingocer
,sgnos erom wef a hguorht detiaw eh oS
:srettam kcaP taerG eht yhw s’tahT
,si ti naht nuf erom tol a sdnuos taht teb I
.tnemssessa riaf a ekil dednuos taht tub—
,si nidloh m’I flow eht tahw
citsaisuhtne yldliw dna ),seliM(
gniwonk ton ekil ,tnet eht ni
,rood eht yb stoob
.ereht gnoleb I taht detnarg rof ti sekat tsuj kcap elohw eht
rewsna taht fo hcum woh swonk ohw esuac ,flow a morf ,lleh rO
,won rehtegot er’ew ,nom’c
,od ot desoppus saw eh sevlow tnereffid ot gniklat eht lla no trats a ekam llew sa thgim ”,ksa ot evah I ,kO“
,srednepsus ,sehtolc ytsud erow mih ediseb flow ehT
etam tnereffid a evah ebyaM
.ssensuoicsnoc tsol luaP dna
htob noitnem ot ton
”,puP ,lleW“ ”.eno siht s’tI“
ylbappotsnu egrahc dna
.sevlow enol retfird
dluow woH“ ”?riaf saw ti knihT ?yeht dluoW“
,sselehtenon ereh tub
.meht dnuora gnilttes saw kcap diaS
.kcapkcab nepo na fo tuo tnegreted yrdnual fo elttob ynit a debbarg
mra eno rednu doowerif fo daolkcurt eritne na ekil dekool tahw gniyrrac dna lla ta gnihton gniraew tsaeb toof-neves eht
,eurtnu t’nsaw hcihw ,dias luaP ”,kcap siht htiw yltnecer ylno …m’I“
.namuh a ekil kool uoy nehw uoy laer eht gnieb pots t’nod uoY
.desu dah dneirfyob sih taht ot ralimis yrev esop a ni ,rac eht fo edis eht tsniaga kcab denael flow ehT
flow rehto eht tlef eh did yeht erofeb tub
?ereht saw ,mih htiw gnieergasid hcum t’nsaw ereht ,tsol dekool luaP thguoht eh fi ,lleW
.deen uoy leef uoy tahw
.txetnoc morf sseug dliw koot dna daeh sih detlit eH ”?rednib a s’tahW
,stnega owt eht neeb ylno dah ereht
,lluf oot saw daeh sih tuB
.rehtohcae rof secalp ekam yeht dna
”?kcaP sniatnuoM enipucroP eht uoy t’nerA“
”.ris ,tsol leef I sseug I“
srewsna eht rof meht deknaht luaP os
,yawrood eht yb gnidnats saw flow rehto ehT .pu dekool luaP
”.dlo oot saw I thguoht I retfa gnol ,fles’m tuoba tol lufrewop a degnahc ydaerlA
.kniht ot ,sllihtoof eht otni pu ,shtoob eht dna stnet eht morf yawa derednaw d’eH .pu dekool luaP
.emoc reve yad taht dluohs
,kcaP taerG eht ni
.regnilsnug a dna nairarbil a neewteb tniop yawflah eht ekil noisserpxe
.mih rof gnivael erew yeht
”.gnorw sa emas eht s’taht fo enon tuB
.snamuh morf denrael yeht
,stoob yobwoc ytfeh dna
,esnesnon gniklat detrats eh dna rekihhctih a pu dekcip I nehw oS
,nitraM dna naD dna seliM gninioj fo aedi eht ekil tlef tI
.lworg fo tnih a htiw ,eno nud eht dehsinif ”,sevlowfiW er’ew os ,seY“ ”.’floW-naM‘
deeps ot uoy detcepxe yeht dna ,peels dna tae ot thgin a sruoh eerht detegdub tog ylno
,etam ot etam ,kcap ot kcap
,llac dluohs I tahw taht si tuB
,tekcop norpa na otni releep dna efink gnirap eht deppils
:yrots siht fo gnitirw eht ni noitatlusnoc dna ecivda dedivorp ohw esoht ot sknaht laicepS  .elbissop sa
.goD fo ecioV eht no
,mih ni ti evah dluow eh fi
,luaP ot eno dessap eH
.rof gnikool er’uoy tahw htiw kcul doog ,dik ,yawynA
,netfo ti ees t’nod I fi neve ’emoh‘ s’taht“
,luaP ta wap a debbaj eh
.eruc a sa gniht hcus on saw ereht
?rehcaerp flowerew fo dnik emos“
.kcap eht fo trap eb ot ,kaeps ot os ,gnir eht otni tah ym worht ot deen t’nod I taht si
”,hsilgnE dlO morf s’tI“
?flow a sa pu werg uoy oS“
”?wonk uoy ,desseug adluow reve I naht detacilpmoc erom hcum os s’ti
ssel tol a era seidob sevlow elamef dna seidob sevlow elam ,hU“
”,dik ,onnud I ,lleW“
,desolc yltneg gnuws rood nibac ehT ”.su fo eno er’uoy
,reywal a llac ot dlot neeb dah
,trohs deppots oravlA
,kaerbtraeh cificepsnon tuoba sesreV
.tleb sih morf gnignah tub ,nrow ton
?skcap rehto emos otni snur eh llit uoy htiw gnola gat luaP tel“
,sredluohs sih derauqs luaP
,evots eht no gnitrofmoc dna mraw gnihtemos dna
.traeh yb ti wenk ylraelc kcap s’flow etihw-ylraen eht llA .lwoh ot tnaw—
.kcab emoc ot detrats llems fo esnes sih llit erehwyna og ot ton esimorp mih edam dna
”,flow a nrob neeb t’ndah I fi …oS“
.ksa ot thguoht neve reven I snoitseuq ot srewsna
,depmuj ohw ,oravlA ot denrut eh
,erew stnerap reh erehw dlihc flow a ksa ot desuap oravlA
,tcatnoc eye edam flow lennalf eht nehw depmuj luaP
”?sretfihsepahs su llac yeht dluow esle yhW
eht tnia I“ .deggurhs namtihW ”.on dna sey
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
htiw devirra d’eh kcap eht tuoba seiteixna siH ”.on
,htuom s’tsoh sih dnuof spil siH
,denialpxe namtihW ”,nehw si trats eht sseug I“
,goderew fo dnik emos spahrep
”.srewsna emos tuo gnikroW“
”?ksa ot deen t’ndluow I“
!gnos gnitsalreve nA
,teef erab dna ,snaej pu taeb
,spleh taht epoh ,hU“
.nihtiw flow rehto eht dewollof eH
,ylwols ,deddon luaP
yllaer uoy tahw oS“
,seye reh dellor flow nud eht ”…on ,lleW“
,edirts gnikaerb tuohtiw gnos dnoces a otni devom yehT
”,on lleW“ ”?dnal ruoy
,pu ti ekow flow eht dna em ni syawla saw taht ebyam
tnaw yllaer uoy lla esuaceb tnaw uoy ecalp tahw llet t’nac uoY .gnignoleb si“ ,kcab sih ta nus gnittes ,gniliar hcrop sih no denael flow krad eht ”,retfa tsul
.oravlA dna ,cidem eht ,seliM htiw enola mih tfel d’yeht won tuB
,elbatpecca s’edis namuh eht ylno taht syas taht yteicos a ni evil uoy dna
s’taht …rof skrow ti su fo esoht rof …dna“
.t'nod I tsael tA
etinarg fo ecaf htooms a no flesreh gninnus ,tlep nud ,flow redlo rehtona htiw
”.krow hcum sa tsuj
.niaga daeh sih detlit luaP
,taht did uoy nehw tub ,kO“
?tuoba sralloc eht era tahw“
,ylisub deggaw liat sih tub
,uoy ksa ylno nac eh siht rof dna ,dedeeccus ylluf ton sseltbuod sah eh siht tA
enimatsihitna fo stohs nettog lla
’rew‘ saw nam rof drow eht ,neht kcaB“
eerf mih tes seliM ”,puP ,efas eB“
,me ot hguone riaf nieb er’uoy kniht yeht fI“
dias uoy“ ,hguoht ,tiaW
.etsat tsellams eht tsuJ .yltneg dehsurb
”-tuB .gnihton ton s’taht dna ,elbatrofmoc erom dna reisae thgir gnitneserp
.ot etaler dluoc eh tniop a tih evah yllanif ot dalg
wonk uoy gniht txen dna ,rehtona ot del aedi eno ,gniyrt tuoba deklat eW
.mih ta deknilb namtihW
.namuh a morf srewsna tsurt t’ndluow I—
,raehrevo dluoc luaP sa raf sA
”uoY roF kcaP taerG eht ni ecalP a s'erehT“
.ot thguo yeht kniht“
.mih ton ,yzarc enog d’ohw eno eht saw I gnikniht ot tog I
.emoh saw eh thginoT .kcap sih htiw
nialpxe ot gniyrt syad
.evisserpmi t’nerew eh ,hturt eht llet oT“
sgatgod dna ralloc a dah eH
seliM elcnU“
.sih dnuof s’eh skniht ohw