,htaerb ytfeh a ni gnikaT
,enihw tniaf a tuo tel miJ
.kcen sih dnuora thgit fracs elprup siht erow eH
”.gnirimda tsuj m’I
.su rednu koohs deb eht sa
”?dloc oot eb t’now uoY“ .delims eH
.etisbew sserP lesaeW eht ta dnuof eb nac dna 0202 yluJ desaeler saw
.egalfuomac etelpmoc yaw-flah siht htiw elbisivni eb dluow em fo trap ylno fi sA
.snalp edam I“
fo skaerb neve erew yehT
.rae sih delbbin dna seye ym dellor I
”seviL ruO fo syaD eht erA esehT“   :yojne esaelP
em tsniaga htaerb peed a ni koot eH
.pord tsal eht pu dekcil I sa ssa sih gnillif xamilc nwo ym
.niaga eert eht ot drawrof mih degdun I dna ,dias I ”,tiaW“
.seye ym desolc dna edisa taht fo lla dehsup I
.tfahs ym gnola gnidils htuom a fo ssentsiom eht leef dluoc I .desolc seye yM
.mih dekcuf I sa drah mih dekorts I
.yawllah ruo fo sllaw eht neewteb gnicnuob eciov sih
wenk reven i ecalp a emoh em derul   revol
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
daeh sih evoba sdnah sih dellup I txeN
.ssa sih gnibbarg
,kcen sih dessik dna ni devom I
.tekcaj sih htaenrednu
.siht no devargne taht teg ot em rof esnes edam ti oS
.repeed ni flesym dehsup I sa
,mih fo pot no despalloc dna sdnah sih fo og tel I ,ylsuoiruf gnitnurG
evol htiw dednelb rouqil ruo
.su gnidnuorrus ygrene fo esnes ddo siht
kcoc ym ,su fo erutcip kciuq a deppans dna enohp llec ym tuo koot I
:em dnuora thgit saw eH
.nips ot demees em dnuora dlrow ehT
,dnuorg eht no tlenk I
”,hguoht suorutnevda siht ton yllamron er’uoY .rebmemer I ,oN“
,sdnuorg wen no ekauqhtrae na detaerc eW
.kcen sih gnikcus detrats dna
.tserof detnuah evisulcxe siht fo renroc eht ni eert a
.seidob ruo rof gnizeerf oot tog dloc eht erofeb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.emit
,deksa eh ”?yako uoY“
.etatsorp sih tsniaga gnihsup kcoc yM
”?tops siht ti saW“
,enim revo delruc gel sih nehw tuB
.ydob elprup denekrad ym htiw gnihsem
.daol ym gnitoohs erofeb semit lareves aera emas eht gnikirtS .daed eht dna su neewteb gnithgil elprup eht saw I
gnislup kcoc sih ,em sdrawot pu ylleb sih dehsup kcab siH
.duola ti daer eh sa em ot pu deklaw ylwols teef siH
.daeherof sih no mih dessik I sa
swap sih debbarg I sa pley toh a tuo tel eH
lriws eht saw eh
.sdnuos taht sa yseehc sA .mih ni gnihtyreve ees I tuB
,eert eht morf nwod smra sih tel I
,yas mih draeh I ”,oliS“
.gnihtyreve no yas lanif eht evah ot dah syawla eH .etamitlU
raey a neeb ylno s'ti wonk i
.ylleb sih otno daol sih tohs kcoc sih ,eloh sih dehsur xamilc ym erofeB
.won detanimulli tsomla demees su dnuora aera ehT
.mih ot resolc devom dna dekrims I
.erac t’ndid ew tey
”.ti revo teg ot evah tsuJ
”?ereh em welb uoy nehw rebmemeR“
.reduol gnitteg snaom sih
!uoy llet t’nac I“
.yretemec eht otni raf su del I
.sdnilb eht hguorht dereep nus eht sa ylsseltroffe tpels miJ
,detnuah dekool ecalp siht ,ecnalg tsrif tA
.dnats thgin eht ni kcab ti tup dna yltfiws xob gnir eht desolc I
,aeY“ .daeh ym koohs I dna
.enog dah ecneidua ruo ,taht ekil dnA
,etartenep ot gniyrt fi sa ,tsehc sih no yltcerid dednal maeb enO
.ssa sih dnuora yltcefrep gnivruc
.kaep sti deraen xamilc ym sa delarips ssarg dna stiripS
.seod syawla tI .raeppa ll’ti
.emarf wodniw eht ni su evoba gnignah bewredips llams A
.mih kcuf ot deunitnoc I ,tneps saw I hguohT
.liart eht no dneb a dednuor eW
.em teem ot esor ylwols eh rethgual fo tif a nI
,enim saw eh tnemom siht nI
.mih depacse snaoM
,liart eht ffo su deklaw I
.koohs sdnilb eht sa wodniw eht hguorht depacse thgil fo seripS
,kcab ti deknay dna daeh sih no riah fo tfut eht ta debbarg I
htuom sih ni kcoc ym dehsup dna nwod tlenk eH
.su gnidnuorrus srehto eht ta gnikool dnuora detrad seye siH
.aera eht ni srac on tsael ta ,dnuora enoyna t’nsaw erehT
.mih ni ees I tahw wonk t’nseod eh taht dna
,nemodba sih gnola deliart seye yM
.maerc deppihw elprup eht I dna
.svetahw tuB .emit htiw elbirret gnikcuf si ohw ereht tuo snamreboD wef eht fo eno ylbaborp m’I
,enil tsal taht daer eh sA   ?em gniyrram fo
.su dnuora gnicnad saw taht wons eht htaeneb dewolg tsomla srae sih ni nworb eht tub ,edistuo yerg saw tI
,su eb dluow taht ,xim a erew ettal allinav a dna redneval fI
,dehceercs eh dnoces toh a nI
em ssik uoy nehw ro ,peels uoy elihw ruf ruoy htaeneb wolg srebme tahw
.tekcop tekcaj ym ni ylmrif deltsen gnir ehT
.rewsna sih rof gnitiaw ,dnah ni gnir
.roolf eht gnipiw detrats dna rekam eeffoc eht ffo tuhs I
.htuom sih otni eugnot ym gnidils ,esolc ni mih thguorb dna
.seye sih dellor dna em ta deralg eH
.epacse dluoc sdrow erom yna erofeb ffo mih tuc tub
”?gniraew uoy era raewrednu fo dnik tahW“
.siht ekil yal ew nehw em fo pot no dednelb lla ,sregnif sih no stops nworb eht
.seidob ruo tsniaga ekips a saw yar hcaE
.shtaerb denethgirf neewteb yas I
.daeh sih evoba meht dleh dna
.yadot taht od dluoc ohw I ylno saw ti tub
.ecaf sih gnitanimulli thgil eht ,rettiwt pu denepo eh ,enohp sih gnibbarG
.evol ,thginot emoh eb tsuJ
,enola yltcefrep erew eW
.nosrep a sa ylno ,oediv DSL s06 emos saw I ekil saw tI
,uoy ot txen ydob mraw a dna steknalb kciht htaenrednu depolevne er’uoy nehw ,naem I
htiw evil ot nosrep tseisae eht t'nia i
.su gnidnuorrus sevael gniyd eht htiw llew dednelb tsomla riah neerg yM
.rettam t’ndid ti tuB .ereht neve erew yeht fi ro ,tnew yeht erehw wonk t’nod I
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
.enim saw reirret a fo llabffulf siht tub ,semitemos driew era sgoD
.repap koobeton fo eceip mils a debbarg dna eloh eht ni dnah sih tup miJ
ruf sih fo etihw-ffo eht gnola deregnil seye yM
,lesaeW yb ”seviL ruO fo syaD eht erA esehT“ saw sihT
.pu ti naelc ot nar I sa em morf depmuj drow ehT ”!kcuF“
”esioN htiw eroM ecnO“
.sliaw enobmort htiw gnigrem htaerb
.pu teg ot dah ew wenk htob ew tub ,niaga peels tsomla dluoc eW
.drah mih dessik dna eert eht tsniaga mih dehsup I
.kcoc ym gnibbarg ,deksa eh ”?ti si tahW“
.thgil gninrom eht ni snetsilg ybur eht ;latem revlis krad eht
.meht detcerruser ew ebyam rO
,deniamer llits wolg ehT
ffo mih dellup I tfahs ym dnuora gag ot detrats eh nehW
.su dnuora lla erew yeht deknilb I tnemom eht dna ,mih tsniaga yllufecrof tsurht I
.setag eht dnoyeb su gnihsup
.ebab ,wonk I yug tseixes eht er’uoy taht pleh t’nac I“
.fo og tel ot tnaw ylerar I taht tnemom a s’tI
,nwonk flesti ekam ot stnaw ti nehw tey
woleb sselpleh yal ydob rebmil siH
,daeherof sih ssik dna ni nael dluoc I erofeb dnA
.kcab mih dezeeuqs I dna ,em dezeeuqs ylleb ym revo depard mra sih
”.reboog ,gninroM“ .mih I dna
?yna gniraew m’I syas ohW“
.thgil fo hctolps ylleb a ot elprup peed morf tnew ydob ym woh detah syawla I
snaej sih otni dnah ym derewol I
,ylyoc dias I ”?ecalp siht rebmemer t’nod uoY“
.rae sih fo ssentfos eht ta gnihctarcs yllufyalp
.dloc saw tI  lesaeW yb
,rae sih ni ”,uoy evol I“ ,detnurG
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
yzarc m’I taht uoy llet ylbaborp d’eh ,siht fo lla mih ksa ot erew uoy fI
.mrots dab a morf sevaw ekil yltneloiv gninoitom emarf eht
.roolf eht revo sllips egduls kcalB .gniwolfrevo top eeffoc eht ees I
seye ruoy edisni dlrow eht ees ton dluoc ohw   sore tub
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.pu teg ot su rof emit s’ti esoppus I“
.desaib dat a m’I ,yas I nac tahw tuB .eno
.detuohs yllacitcarp eh ”,tuo llup t’noD“
.tnemom a rof mih koot noisufnoC
.ereh ynam yb neesnu ygrene na gnitaname
”seviL ruo fo syaD eht era esehT“
.detaefed syas eh ”!eniiF“
,sgel sih depparw snaej ynnikS
.ssa sih otni drah gniog
.erusnu ,dednopser eh
,dias eh ”?melborp ruoy si tahW !dog ym hO“
.ylgnisaet deksa eh ”?yddad ,drah em kcuf annoG“
.gnippot yragus a s’ti kniht ot ekil I tub—
erom stnemom wef a mih edisni deyats I ,emac eh retfa nevE
,enalp a no odriew emos m’I fi sa em ta gnikool
erew yehT .meht llac uoy tahw erac t’nod I .stsohG .stiripS
,detrats eh ”,ebab yeH“
.ti fo thgis eht ta tlem d’I elprup ro neerg erow eh fI
eeffoc htiw ni xim ot drah si neerg—
.kcid ym no gnihtemos saw erehT
.yllufetsat tuo gnippird muc ,ssa desu sih fo owt ro cip rehtona deppans I
.ot tnaw yeht nehw raeppa ylno stsohG
”.mraw htob su peek nac I kniht I“
.mih ta pu dekool I dna
.kcab sih ot mih gnihsup
.evila emoc ot deen eht tlef yeht sseug I
.trihs dna tekcaj ym ffo gnikat ,yllufyalp dias I
”.uoy rof gnihtemos tog I
.ydob sih fo hcra eht gnirimda
ssarg nezorf ,neerg
.ti edisni gnihtemos s’erehT“
,ssem a saw moor ehT
.drawpu detsurht dna ,mih saw ti gniwonk ,daeh s’miJ debbarg dna seye ym denepo I
.noitpircsni eht daer dna gnir eht fo edis eht no slluks eht fo eno ssorca
,rae sih ni derepsihw dna em ot esolc mih dellup I
,noitom emas eht ni nihc sih gnilzzun ,niaga kcen sih dessik I
.dah ew yks eht fo weiv yna gnirevoc
.rebmuls gninrom ylrae sih ot denruter eh erofeb ”,uoy evol I“ na derettum ylipeels eH
gnillup ,delialf I ,yletaidemmI
.yawa gniklaw detrats ew dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.kcoc sih gnibbarg ydob sih nwod dehtooms dnah yM
”…era uoy taht yaw eht uoy era kcuf eht yhW“
,su revo demool seert ehT
.ereh erew ew emit tsrif eht ekil su gnihctaw seye leef dluoc I hguoht neve
riah ym tuoba syas taht tahw wonk t’nod I
.eert eht tsniaga muc sih gnitoohs kcoc sih
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,denepo ylwols seye siH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,daeh sih fo tfut eht gnola dnah ym deliart I
,llaw eht tih ti emit hcaE
.ydob sih ffo stnap sih deppirts I nehw ssa sih dehsal ria llihc eht nehw derevihs eH
.ecaf sih no sllab ym detser I
.spih sih debbarg I sa ria eht ni deohce snaom siH
?yug siht evol ton dluoc ohw esuaceb evol htiw dellif tey ,deniarD
.ssilb fo dlrow siht ni
”.krod ,emit siht ti ekat ll’I“
.bmil eht evoba ti depard dna
.em ta pu derats eh sa wol gnignah sdil
;ti eb dluow siht sseug I“
,swodahs was I thguoht I ,tnemom a roF
tnetsixe-oc erew ssenipeels dna noitsuahxe fi sa ,etats ymaerd taht ni llits saw eciov siH ”.eeffoc deen I“
.ereht dnuora erehwemoS .hsi-thgiE .thgie dnuora ylbaborp saw ti derugif I ,saw nus eht thgirb woh yb tub ,saw ti emit tahw llet t’ndluoc I
.hcaeb eht demmals evaw wen a
.etuc ’nikcuf s’eh shgual eh nehw nevE
.shtaerb dehsur htaeneb dias eh ”,ynroh siht eb d’uoy wonk t’ndid I“
.su dnuora gniwolg ylwols erew seert eht fi sa tlef ti ,dnuora gnikooL
dna sevael nworb ehT
.eeffoc eht trats ot yawa gniklaw yas I ”,timmaddoG“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
em deliops ev'uoy
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.tnemom eht ni ereht yal eW
.dednal eh sa hctaw ot gnitseretni syawla saw tI .polf lluf eno ni hcuoc eht no dednal eH
.dlrow eht rof pu mih gnivig ton m’I
,tsafkaerb trats ,eeffoc teg dluohs I rehtehw no gnitabed moor eht dnuora dekool I
.msicitore fo tca siht ni rehtegot dednelb seidob ruo
seenk ym dnuora thgit stnaP
.kcab ym ta gnibbarg wap sih
.ni emac ”etamitlu“ erehw si hcihw ,thgir syawla saw eh yllufyalP
,demialcxe eh ”,sey kcuF“
,kcab derepsihw dna kcen ym dessik dna ni denael eH
.yggorg erew sdrow yM
.mih gniyalp erew sdnah thgir eht nehw htoomS
.ratiug citsuoca na fo seton ekil eugnot sih ffo llef sdrow ehT
”.esruoc gnikcuf fO“
,saw reirret siht sa lufyalP
taht erow eh nehw devol syawla I
.edisni llits rebmem gnidaf tey drah ym
.)em nikcuf t’nia ti :hsalfswen( reixes ro retuc saw kcuf eht ohw gnizilanif fo yaw etuc ruO
.sserP lesaeW fo eduD ehT dna
.nepo ti pilf dna xob llams a tuo llup I ,dnats thgin eht morF
.wonk dluow I ,ytsat saw ti dnA
.ni thgir dehsur dna tips htiw kcoc ym debul I
.serutsap retfos ot gnitemmulp duolc a erew ydob sih fi sA
.ti fo hguone teg t’ndluoc kcoc ym dna
.drah-imes llits kcoc sih
bmuht ym bur I
,yllacainam gnihgual ,em swollof eH
.ereht mih deit dna
”.yson ,thginot ees ot evah tsuj ll’uoY
.etammaet a ot dessap gnieb llabteksab a ekil gnicnuob tsehc sih ,delkcuhc eH
”.aedi dab a eb t’ndluow emirc eht fo enecs eht ot gninruter derugif I“
,ruf sih fo ssentfos eht woh evol did I tuB
,gnihctaw ,su dnuora
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,mih desaet hteet ym sa em htaeneb gnitlem ydob sih leef dluoc I
,emit ni nezorf gniyatS .enog s’tI
.sllab sih ot nwod liart llams a gnikam ,tsehc sih ot pu welf muc sih fo sdnartS
”,dnuor rehtona rof ydaer m’I lleW“
,seye sih ni airohpue eht ees dluoc I
rohtua & teop xnitaL ,reeuQ a si ohw ,lesaeW yb
.sserd ot woh swonk syawla eH  ***   ”.ydaer s’eeffoC“
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
,desaet I ”,kcid ym dehcuot htuom ruoy tnemom eht wenk uoY“
.moor gnivil eht otni gniklaw
.ssa sih otni peed flesym dehsup I sa demialcxe eh ”!kcuF“
.emem gnikcuf a gnikcimim
.tluda elbisnopser a sa od ot desoppus er’uoy sgniht eht lla ,rewohs
”?drayevarg siht ta gniod ew era tahw dnA
***   ?yug siht evael dluoc kcuf eht ohW
ylleb sih degguh knat siH
shtnom wef a rof rehtegot denioj ylno ev'ew dna
no senihs nus ehT
yrteop fo koob tsetal siH
,liart eht pu dekcil dna ni denael I
.retal ro renoos pu ekaw ot gniog saw I wonk ot dah eh
.kciuq kcab deppals yob eht
.etairporppa s’taht sseug I os elpoep daed fo tol a dloh seod ti tub
.deb eht ffo gnippoh dna ssa sih fo tuo kcoc ym
”.thginot snalp evah ew tegrof t’noD ?ebab ,yeH“
ronoh eht em od uoy dluow
,em otni dellor eh tnemom eht pu gninaelc fo thguoht eht dehsup I tub
kcen sih ffo fracs sih dellup sdnah yM
?thgir ,evael ot tnaw uoy dluow yhw
.knis eht tsniaga kcab denael dna dnuora denrut I ,dewerb eeffoc eht sA
.srae sih gnigassam ylwols bmuht ym
.em ta pu dekool dna ffo dellup neht
.ti sdrawot daeh ym devom I ”.kool a ekat oG
,em dnuora smra sih depparw miJ
.deb ym fo trofmoc eht eva el ot tnaw ton em ekam ot hguone dloc ,tsael tA
.elkcuhc a htiw dias eh ”,emas eht kool tsom
”.gnorw tsuj er’uoY ?reboog tsael eht ekil m’I .os kniht t’nod I“
,dehcterts eh sa mih fo lla gnitaluspacne ,thgir tsuj ydob sih tih thgil ehT
.tsehc ym gnilzzun
si yrots s’yadoT dna
msicitore fo liatkcoc a era ew
,thgit saw eh sgninrom tsom
.osrot ym htiw gnihsem ruf nworb dna etihw sih ,tfahs ym fo esab eht ta nwod mih dleh I
.nruter ni sdrow eht denaom eh dna
.ssem ym saw eh tub ,ssem a saw eH
yawa dellup I sa ylmrif mih dekorts dnah yM
ksa ot evah i os
.ylkciuq kcoc sih gnibbarg
.enog erew yeht deknilb I nehw tub ,dnuora gnidnats seidob deyerg
”?naem uoy od lleh yag ni tahW .t’nod ew oN“
.tfahs kciht sih dekrow llits sdnah ym tey ,ygrene citore lla fo flesti deniard ydob redneval yM
.hguorht gniwolb dniw llams eht htiw welf ruf egieb siH
.tsap eht htiw ecneirepxe ym neeb syawla s’tahT
.rae sih delbbin dna ni denael I ,tsurht spih ym sA