seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,floWcaM boR yb meop a uoy gnidaer si yralC-ttocS nosidaM ,yadoT
.seye sih er'yeht dneterp tub
.seirots neewollaH gnidaer er’ew keew siht dna
’detnuaH sI meoP sihT‘
.goD fO tsohG ehT dellac
?sddo eht era tahW
,floWcaM boR yb
.gnivil sih saw tahT
.ton naht ekila erom era yrecros dna gnilletyrots taht devresbo neeb gnol sah tI
tfel era taht sdrow eht era esehT
.htaed sih si sihT
erehwemos si eh yks eht si
”detnuaH sI meoP sihT“ saw sihT     .dniheb
.esrevinu gnivil eht revo rewop
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb uoy rof daer
.sdog fo-draehnu ot ratla sih si sihT .ylsuomuhtsop
.doolb sih si sihT
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.rood eht edistuo tfel ,seohs sih erew esohT
,egaugnal yrev siht fo smrof tneicna tsom eht ni taht gnihton rof ton si tI
,lacihpargoibotua era smeop lla ton taht timda lliw ,desserp fi ,ohw
.ydob sih si sihT
.egassem a si sihT
.egap yrruFoS sih no
.ezis lausunu fo hteet sih era esehT
.htaerb fo tuo tliub eh taht esuoh eht si sihT
noitatneserp neewollaH laiceps a fo trap sa
,separg deleep era esehT
flowcaM boR yb ,”detnuaH sI meoP sihT“   .goD fo tsohG ehT …no thginot
.doow fo tuo devrac yeht taht traeh sih si sihT
fo alumrof a dna ,dlot yrots a htob tnaem ’lleps‘ drow eht
taht dnA ,dnim sih fo
.mih raeh yeht did ereH
,ydobemos yb devieceR eb ot tnaem spahreP
.erom on meht sdeen eh hguoht ,sehtolc sih era esehT
.edistuo gniltsihw-a
ni flesruoy rof taht fo hturt eht egduj tuB
,deihporta etiuq ,ssenlufepoh sih si sihT
,dniw eht tsuj s'taht dnA
,reh dniheb si liat esohw