,no sevom esrevinu ehT  .taerg sa
,stsaeB deziliviC ni deraeppa tsrif hcihw
.llenk s'lleb htaed nmelos eht sdeeh roN
,denekrad saH nus gnirednaw eht semit derdnuh derdnuh neT
,ylwols reve devil efil A
,regnol hcuM devivrus
,yrc etarepsed a ot reve snetsil roN
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb uoy rof daer
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.llaf lliw dne rettib eht mohw morf suht oS
delaripsne'ht otnI denrut slobmys enacra ni tirw si efil yM wonk I tsael ta trohs sworg emit ym hguoht dnA ;denruter
syas gnitirw taht
dellac ,II emulov
,htrae tsenoh eht sliopseD
.llehs ym fo snrettap
yrots sselega na sllet tI
,orevO ovitlA yb
yrotsih tneicna ehT
.elat rettib dna ,wols
,”nainolehC sthguohT“
deman eb sevlesmeht dluow ohw lla fO etaf eht dna
,sesiotrot dekcol-llehs eht ,eW
”nainolehC sthguohT“
,naM dellac ecar tratspu ,lertsaw ,ytsah tahT
.llew lluf dlot si
,thgilrats eht ni teY
,gnidlofnu gnol A kaeps taht senil gnitsiwt eht sllehs ruo nopU liaf tuohtiw gnipeek ,gnihctaw
,orevO ovitlA yb si meop s’yadot dnA
,”nainolehC sthguohT“   yojne esaelP
htob erA ,tsaf devil eno
,lla neddort ylsselerac evah mohw nO psa na thgim sa dlrow eht lla snosioP .yks eht ,aes eht
,ecaparaC nevarg ylegnarts O
,llehs a nop' nevarg
nainolehC sthguohT  orevO ovitlA yb meop a
,lleps derettum a raeh ot ton sesuap dnA
.reh dniheb si liat esohw
,psag elgnis a tsuj sa trohs os efil htiW
saw sihT     .tsap eht eb ot
demood tsuj gnol ere
,ecart tuohtiw dehsinav
.llew uoht kaeps