.esroH retfa desahc ohw
.ti dnuora yaw on si ereht tub
,dias yeht ”,rehcaeT O“
.)’drol‘ osla( soiryk keerG eht dna
,gnillewd a edam ereht dna
*  .noitaerc desselb ot ytrap emoceb yeht yaw siht ni rof
,rehtom sti rof yletarepsed gniprihc
- )dedda sisahpme( ”?rewsna eht ot strap eerht era ereht taht won dnatsrednu uoy oD“ - noitseuq siht fo noisrev nwonk ylnommoc erom ehT(
*  ).krow siht fo epocs eht dnoyeb si noitaluceps hcuS
”?morf emoc ew od erehw“
,repeews-teerts eht
,dnal eht fo tser eht gnillif
.srettam yrdnus no noinipo sih raeh ot ediw dna raf morf levart dluow ynam erehw
,LABAKKU ,ytic tsrif eht gnisiar
,dlrow eht htiw tnetnoc saw aziakaerE woN  .erom ecno
,aziakaerE emac
;serusaelp eseht mih htiw erahs ot
,repeews-teerts eht ksa ot devloser yeht ,tnemugra eht emuser naht rehtar dna
.emoh wen a sevlesmeht ekam dna elttes dluoc ylimaf sih dna itnI erehw ,aes eht dna sniatnuom eht neewteb sdnal sih fo trap driht a dna
.htrae eht fo stiurf eht fo kcip tsrif dah tsedle sa ohw ,beN morf dia thguos
,dias yeht ”,rehcaeT O“
.syaW eht fo dnal eht ot sdog eht yb delixe si dna ,nerdlihc sih dna itnI srethguals kkU ,seirots lanigiro eht fo eno nI
.erom ecno ,nanuJ
,sgnilbis eht desselb ytirepsorp ,emit a roF
.repmet sih tsol nanuJ ,siht tA
.egar htiw dellif saw kkU dna
,rewsna siht htiw deifsitasnu erew selpicsid emoS
.sralohcs ot nwonk neeb gnol evah hcihw fo htob
.meht egnellahc ot snosaer lacihposolihp dah evah yam ro
;ssenhsiloof ruoy htiw repeek-sdnuorg eht rehtob oG
,niawt ni sniatnuom tfelc gatS dna noiL selttab rieht ni
yojne esaelP  .3OA no
,nrobtsriF eht fo tsegnuoy ehT
.doG gnipeelS eht fo erugif eht nopu
,mih deffuber beN tuB
.aes eht fo stiurf eht fo kcip tsrif dah tsedle-dnoces sa ohw
,goD emaceb floW dna
em ot gninruter fo daetsni sdnal wen kees tsum uoy roF
,eniwtretni seiks eht dna sdnas eht erehw ot dleifa raf derednaw dna
,nerdlihc sih dna itnI ssorca emac yeht ,yaw eht no tuB
,woC emaceb xO dna
,retsam rieht erofeb yreuq rieht thguorb dna elpmet eht ot denruter yeht os ,siht htiw deifsitasnu erew selpicsid emos llitS
naM fo nigiro eht tuoba noissucsid a gnivah erew stneduts emos ,yad enO  rettiR yb
,dnal siht dna ytic siht morf uoy hsinab I
- slatrom dna sdog fo erutan cilcyc eht fo noitatneserper a sa tnaem si ti taht tseggus elaT s’nanuJ tuoba seiroeht gnidaeL .rohpatem eht ot denethgilne emoceb yeht litnu meht nopu etatidem stneduts taht noitnetni eht htiw
,sloot ’stnerap rieht htiw gniyalp nerdlihc sa era ew rof
”riK“ dna ”beN“ seman eht fo
,yad eno taht deneppah os tI
,dednah-ytpme yawa mih tnes ,oot ,riK tuB
,smlaer eht ssorca derettacs syawla ton erew naM fo nerdlihc ehT
,relevart wollef ruoy
.tliub dah nem taht seitic eht dna sdleif eht dna sdoow eht revo gniraos
!sretsgnuoy toidI“
.yhposolihp dna wal tuoba desruocsid eh nehw yltnetni gninetsil dna
,gnidnatsrednu ton ,stneduts ehT
,etartsigam eht dias ”,dneirf yM“
;sroloc dna sdrow htiw gniyot dna stnemgif gnitaerc ni
,tnenitnoc eht nopu tlips naM fo doolb eht ees ot gnihsiw ton ,yeht tuB
,dnob ruo fo ssendercas eht dna noitats ym fo rewop eht yb ,suhT .)ton ma(
.eman emas eht fo dog nus
,cisum deyalp etartsigam eht nehw gnignis
murag ron yenoh rehtien taht tnemeergasid a ot emac yeht nehw
.htrae eht nopu nevrac deed regnol on saw drow rieht dna
)1102( nivuaC hguohtla
,labakkU fo ytic eht fo toor lacigolomyte eht smrof ,esruoc fo ,”kkU“
,drib a saw eh taht tmaerd eH
,edis sih ot denruter syawla ti taht os
,syaW eht rof edor yeht dna
.nanuJ dias ”?rewsna eht ot strap eerht eht won dnatsrednu uoy oD“
,mra s’etartsigam eht delzzun worc eht dnA
.elbat a nopu mih dial dna
,itnI ot enod dah eh sa ,mih deffuber beN tuB
.nekaw dluow eh thguoht enon hcihw morf ,peels peed ,peed a otni llef eH
,slauqe rehto hcae dellac llits tsaeb dna tnalp dna nam dna gnuoy saw dlrow eht nehW
sgnilbiS tsriF eht fo efirts eht gnirb dna
- su nethgilne yarp“ ,dias yeht ”,madam raeD“ .oail-laB
,meht dloh ot hguone ton saw dnal eht ,hguone noos dna
,gnits dna nroht dna walc werg dne siht ot dna
.hguorht teg dluoc esroh sih erofeb egassap taht ffo desolc sdog eht ton dah
,riK teem ot delias itnI os dna
,lianS dna gulS morf sgel eht laets edepilliM was aziakaerE dnA .peed eht fo tuo sresyeg morf elahW ythgim desiar xebI dna
”?morf emoc ew od erehw
sdnah tfos htiw pu mih dekcip nam yldnik a erehw
,lli ylevarg nekat saw etartsigam eht ,gninrom enO
,ekila elttac dna nerdlihc dna nemow htrof evord yeht dna
,od tsum I tahw em sniap ti dna
,dias yeht ”,ris raeD“
,retsam rieht fo modsiw eht tuo thguos dna
.erutaretil rof noissap a htiw yksuh lacisum a ,rettiR yb
,ecitluop deliaf a ynam ekam ,skoob sih revo erop ot dah etartsigam eht os dna
,gninnuc s’retnuh sih nekat dah
ecnelis saw egasiv esohw
”.ti ekam uoy tahw si morf emoc uoy erehW“ :dias nanuJ
,noitalsnartsim a si
si yrots s’yadoT dna
,sdleif eht ot etsaw dial dna emac thguord drah a tuB
,mih deffuber oot riK dna
,dlrow eht morf nwardhtiw tey ton dah ohw
.revewoh ,evitaluceps ylerem si ecnalbmeser sihT
”.sevlesmeht naht rehto gnihtyna htiw detutitsbus eb ot tnatropmi oot“ demeed era yeht sa
.nekorb gniw sti htiw
,rebmuls siht fo oot ekatrap mrof s’aziakaerE nopu emoc ohw lla dnA
draytruoc s’etartsigam eht ni dednal worc gnuoy a
.sdog eht gnidnetta ot denruter eh nehT
.ti dlohpu ot evas eciohc on dah
,floWcaM boR si sihT
,ytic eht evoba raf esuoh decarret a ni devil eH
.snialp tsav eht fo sdreh eht ot sthgir dah
;xO retfa desahc ohw
,sdreh sih fo trap driht a itnI ot evag eh dna ,ycrem htiw dellif saw traeh s’kkU
,ti htiw dnob gnorts a demrof emit siht revo dna
KKU FO HTARW EHT ELAT S’OAIL-LAB  :ylper s’oail-laB saw sihT
,yamsid dna regna ni detalulu dna
”.morf emoc ew erehw wonk ton od llits ew tub
,sdnalemoh rieht dnoyeb satled elitref eht delttes nerdlihc s’beN
”.yrtsihpos rof emit on evah I
,itnI deman saw ohw
.ssap ot emoc ees ton lliw lios eht fo ew hcihw sgniht dna enog gnol sgniht fo gnimaerd ,llits speels dna
,emit tsrif eht rof sgniw sti daerps ot gninrael
.dnal eht fo ecaf eht nopu ecneloiv a saw ecnarettu yreve dna
.htaed s’etartsigam eht litnu strap esoht ni niaga nees reven saw dna
erehw ,dnal eht nopu dezag aziakaerE dna ;))7991 trebmuH(
,drib rehtona htiw elbbauqs a otni gnitteg ,dnuorg eht ta gnikcip
,syaW eht otni meht gnisahc ,mih erofeb meht evord eH
,gnilgdelf a saw eh taht tmaerd eH
,gnilaeh fo tra eht ni erew shtgnerts sih fo enon tuB
).dednuof evah ot dias si oreh eht hcihw
ilabakkU eht fo ytied rotaerc dna feihc ehT(
.xo dna kcabesroh no snialp eht tuohguorht daerps s’kkU dna ,saes eht ssorca deyenruoj nerdlihc s’riK
, kkU teem ot tnew itnI os dna
,sdreh rieht niatsus ot hguone hcir lios eht ron
,rebmuls sih morf ekowa etartsigam eht nehW
tsedle-driht sa dna
,worc eht dneirf sih dnif ot wodniw sih denepo eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,repeek-sdnuorg eht ,nuziK deksa evah ew“
sthgiled sih ot detaerter naM elihw
;nik ffo-gnurps sih htiw yal dna
,yldrawrofthgiarts detneserp era seirogella gnidnuofnoC
floW retfa desahc eh taht naM dessessop os thgiled ,daetsni tub
.reviled ot yb emac ehs burg wen revetahw nwod gnilbbog
.egrahc wen sih rof ylluf erac dluoc eh erofeb srelaeh htiw tlusnoc dna
,naM ot nedloheb gnieb ,yeht dna
;mlaer sih fo sredrob wen eht gnitcepsni
,yawa saw eh elihw sdnal s’kkU edavni ot deripsnoc yeht oS
,kcihc gnuoy a saw eh taht tmaerd eh ,peels taht nI
,nerdlihc sih dna seviw sih derehtag
.htaed fo egde eht ot thguorb erew elpoep ynam taht hcus
naM morf naM tilps floW taht osla was aziakaerE dnA .umE morf sgniw eht laets taB dna
,sdrow sih dedeeh stneduts ehT
.hceepS sih fo trap tsom eht niater ot mih dewolla dna
dekaeuqs dna delwem dna delwoh meht fo lla dna
,siht fo draeh kkU nehW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,segrahc sih rof elbatiusnu snoisrev htob thguoht evah yam ,seirots eseht delipmoc ohw reitruoc eht ,oanuR .daetsni ’dlrow wen‘ eht ot mih gnihsinab
.gnieb lavemirp fo gnos a rehtegot evow
,htorw emoceb saw eh
neht tpels aziakaerE
.ti dnem ot detpmetta dna ni ti koot
,nedrag desolcne na otni gniw nekorb a fo niap gnibbats eht htiw gniylf
”.niaga reve yrc ruoy raeh ro egamulp ruoy ees ot reven
”LABAKKU FO SELAT EERHT“
WORC EHT DNA ETARTSIGAM EHT ELAT S’NANUJ  :dias nanuJ tahw saw sihT
,swolb htiw setupsid rieht evloser ot denrael serutaerc eht oS
ylluf meht dleiw ot dewolla eb yam ew yad eno taht sepoh eht ni
.mehT dehtrib dah ohw sdog eht rof ecnerefed fo tuo
”?sevlesmeht edam ohw nem eht ro ,su edam ohw sdog eht
.lesnuoc dna dia kees ot sgnilbis sih ot welf yletaidemmi dna
,seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
noissucsid eht dnepsus ot devloser yeht ,pihsdneirf rieht fo ekas eht roF .egaussa dluoc
.sdleif rieht gnimrots dna sesuoh rieht gnikcasnar
,erutaerc yreve fo tuo droW eht dekohc dna emac
,noitisop sih sprusu dna mih fo suolaej sworg kkU tub ,delixe si ohw
,aes eht dna sniatnuom eht neewteb sdnal eht ot denifnoc erew nerdlihc s’itnI tuB
.elpmet eht ni ,nanuJ
:morf emoc ew od neht erehW“ :deilper
.denethgilne erew stneduts eht dnA  ).)8881(
yhtroweton si aziakaerE ,noehtnap
”.deifsitas eb llahs uoy neht yllufepoh dna ,neht ,elat a uoy llet em tel ,emoC“
,meht fo tuo enog dah hceepS rof :dne on ot tub
,rewoP saw gnikaeps dna ,hceepS saw ereht
yoj hcus ekat elpoep yhw si siht dnA
,htlaeh ot kcab worc eht desrun eH
,dlrow wen a fo sniatnuom eht otni ,niaga tuo meht dewollof evah dluow dna
,snevaeh eht ot koot
elihW .werg seilimaf dna senutrof rieht dna
,elcyc sruoH fo mooL lluf eht gnidulcni
,eman rieht naht rehto hceeps fo trap yna gnisu ot derrefer reven era yeht taht ni
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,syaW eht fo dnal eht ni elttes kkU did neht ylnO
,erutaerc roop eht no ytip gnikat ,etartsigam ehT
ELAT S’NUZIK  :ylper s’nuziK saw sihT
itnI si ti ,yrots rehto eht nI
.naok tsihdduB eht ot ralimis dna doirep modgniK elddiM lacissalc eht ot nommoc
;dnal eht nopu taf nworg dah ohw
,yaws sdloh esuaC ron emiT rehtien erehw ecalp eht ni
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer ,rettiR yb
,nem fo seidob eht ni sevlesmeht gnidnif ,sdog eht taht
,selatklof tnereffid owt fo ehcitsap dezitinas a si siht taht stseggus sisylana citsiugniL(  .meht htiw
,tuo dnapxe nerdlihc sih did ereht morF
”labakkU fo selaT eerhT“
aes eht dna dniw eht dna htrae eht sa denetsil dna
ton ma I erehw tirips ym yrrac tsum uoy dna ;)em ot(
”?morf emoc ew od erehw - su nethgilne yarp“
.edistuo seert eht ni emit siht lla detiaw dah ohw
kkU oS  .dnal egnarts a ni wena trats dna evael sih ekat thgim kkU taht os syaW eht denepo osla
.egdelwonk dna ,ssenriaf ,modsiw sih rof dnal eht tuohguorht nwonk saw ohw etartsigam lufrewop a saw ereht ,ecnO
,noiger sudnI eht ot ecnerefer a ylekil tsom si ”itnI“
.mood rieht eb dluow htaed dna noitavrats taht erom ecno raef ot nageb yeht dna
nref gnilgnarts htiw tnapmar sdleif dna kcor gniliob fo saes eht dimA
selbarap lacihposolihp fo mrof eht sekat elaT s’nanuJ(
”labakkU fo selaT eerhT“ saw sihT
,su rof tnaem si tahw dna era uoy ohw won wonk I“
,syaW eht revo hctaw doog tpek yeht dna
,oail-laB deksa evah ew dna
stsaef s’rehto hcae ta gninid dna sdnal emas eht ni gnillewd
,modsiw rieht daerps ot redro ni emoh rieht morf traped ylbativeni tsum
dnal eht ni doof fo tnaw a saw ereht dna
*  ).noitaterpretni siht no sliated erom rof 461 .p ,)1002( sruoH fo kooB s’oanuR ni noitaniviD egA-eznorB :semiT eht fo stehporP ,suidigE eeS
,nuziK ot meht koot sgel rieht dna
)’drol‘( ben naitpygE eht ot
.repeek-sdnuorg eht
notruB yb deziralupop
.ssecorp eht ni sevles eroc rieht ot nruter ot eslupmi eht gnitsiser
nacnI eht ot refer yam ti taht tseggus ot ecnedive gnisirprus sedivorp
,stsaerb dna sgel dna ecaf s’rehtorb sih fo ytuaeb eht yb derutparne ,taht os
.itnI ot enod dah ehs sa
.deb ot eriter ot dah dna
,nik morf nik reves ot htao na erows ,htarw sih ni ,kkU oS
tnuh eht morf flesmih tcartsid dluow naM
.ot tnow era nik esolc sa rehtegot sesuoh taerg gnidliub dna
,soahc siht fo gnirit ,aziakaerE nehT
ytiralimis eht eton )7991 trebmuH ,1002 suidigE( sralohcs emoS(
,sgnilbis sa rehto hcae dedrager ecno nrobtsriF eht rof
floW mohw morf ,naM nopu ytip koot aziakaerE dnA .semod-erusaelp dna sdrayeniv dna sekoy tliub dna
,sniatnuom eht ni tlewd ohw sdog eht gnikovni
.dias eh ”,nerdlihc ylliS“ .dehgis nanuJ
tuo ro ni rednaw sdnim suoiruc tsel