,denoitseuq eb ot trawreG ot denruter eb lliv uoY“
”,rohpatem elbatpecca na si tahT“
rehtoM“ ,tnecca yvaeh a ni detuohs dna
modnar os tnempiuqe fo elip a gnilaever
murd nori egral a ot detcennoc saw hcihw
taoc aes dezirebbur a fo sniamer dedderhs eht htiw depparw ylitsah seriw eht
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”?gnirb uoy od swen tahW“
kcab pets a koot eh nehT
,emac egnahc taht nehw
.edis eht revo stoidi ytiruceS etatS eseht llor em pleH .dooG“
”.su naht retteb meht edam dna
.bir a no gnihctac edalb eht fo egde eht
,gninthgil siht derots dna detareneg ev’uoy ecno ,oS“
.enips reh otni gniggid
”.gnihton rof saw ,doolb siht fo lla
”,skcor eht ni neddih
.thgif eht gnirud werc llams reh htiw revoc rednu deyats dah ehs erehw
,sevots doow rof deen eht tuohtiw
taht tnatropmi denmad os s’taht gniht taht ni si
”?melborp eht s’tahW“
”?detpecretni s’ti fi pihs ym dnefed nac uoy kniht uoy oD
neeb sah trawreG
,selbatsnoc owt no dednal ehs sa niap fo yrc laer yrev
dehsael ylevitceffe reh gnivael drows kcuts reh ot yrettab eht morf gninnur eriw denmad eht
.etarc eht nepo yrp ot gniyrt detrats dna
,erus saw ehs ,tseb rieht od dluow noegrus ehT
elttil a niatpac eht gnivig
,gninrut era seriw reppoc eht nehW“
,efil ym htiw uoy dnefed lliw I“
.ylkaelb dias reffaG-dnoM
,pihs ograc a rof tsaf si remmiksdniW“
,edalb s’acceB fo htgnel eht gnola gninnur skraps eht was eh sa
”,niaga desaeler eb nac ,derots si ti ecno ,yticirtcele ehT“
.sedarmoc gniniamer sih fo eno tsniaga gnilbmut mih gnidnes dna
.ylneddus deworruf worb siH
,gniliar eht revo drawkcab llef ehs sa yrc duol a tuo gnittel ,delbmuts acceB
.remmiksdniW drawot yaw sti gniffuhc
,kcatsekoms sti morf gnisir skraps fo tnuoma suoigidorp eht ot eud elbisiv ylno
”,dniheb morf pu gnimoc rettuc eunever trawreG a tog ev’eW“
,reffaG-dnoM ralohcS ,tsitneics trawreg gnitcefed eht trocse ot noissim a no
.yllacinocal deilper elbatsnoc eht
draob lliv eV !etats ez tsniaga semirc rof detnav nezitic trawreG a gnitropsnart yllagelli era uoY !lessev yrtnuoC
”.net spahrep ,ezis taht taoB“ .deggurhs ehS
gnisluvnoc dna gnippord ylneddus nexiv eitraw‘ eht
”.uoy ot mih rewol ll’eW !no dloH“
gninthgil a htiw rettuc taht paz ot taht esu t’nac uoy ytip a s’ti hguohT“
.yrettab eht ot edalb eht morf gninnur
”?deraperp era yeht nehw ,flesruoy yb meht kcatta ot dnetni uoy woN“ .dias reffaG-dnoM
”,daed etiuq ton tub ,snrub ronim emos spahrep ,yldab dekcohS“
,tsehc reh ta thgir
,yadot nees eb nac tahw naht tnereffid os serutaerc fo senob eht dnif ew yhw s’tahT
,tnemugra ronim a retfA
,denialpxe eh ,lworg deyonna reh tA
,pihs siht dnefed lliw I“
,ydoolb reh pu gnidloh ,yllacinori delims acceB
,delbasid ylefas saw ehs litnu reh pota elip tsuj dluoc yeht ,dezilaer acceB ,llef ehs fI
gniliar trop s’rettuc eht gnola dedworC
,dlrow eht fo epahs eht htiw deifsitas saw ehs erofeb semit ynam deirt sseddoG rehtoM eht taht thguat saw I“
.yot cifitneics evisnepxe na tsuj
,yltcerid ,eno siht ekil pihs a fo srelleporp eht nrut ot desu eb neve dluoc tI
.drawkcab ylsselepoh saw , sretsamdrows ciahcra sti dna ,yrtnuoC rehtoM eht taht thguat neeb syawla dah I“
.deksa ehs ”?uoy era ohw dnA“
”.elpoep ruoy fo erom yna llik ot hsiw t’nod I“ .mih dlot acceB
.desruc acceB ”,kraD dna dloC“
.ylmirg deddon nexiv redlo ehT .deksa acceB
”.eganoipse fo noicipsus dnu ,evitiguf a gnidia rof uoy tserra dnu lessev ruoy dnuopmi ot ,uoy
.dica ciruhplus fo gniknits dna rehtegot deriw lla
.eerf edalb reh gnillup yllanif ni dedeeccus acceB sa
.tleb reh no htaehs ot hguone efas ti gniredner
,ylikahs teef reh ot gnisir saw ohw sreciffo wollef sih fo eno ta nwod dekool eH
srotcetorp-toof rebbur eht ot sknaht ydaets kced nedoow tew eht no pirg reh
,tfel elbatsnoc enO .neveS
.dednamed eh ”!ylkciuq ,llenhcs ,em ot ti gnirB“ ”.drows
,esuohleehw eht morf degreme niatpac s’rettuc ehT
.egatnavda reh ot yrettab eht fo mutnemom eht gnisu ,teef reh ot llor ot elba saw ehs ,yletanutroF
”.slanimirc etucexe dna erutrot ot sriahc deifirtcele
.dloh ograc eht otni nwod gnidael hctah eht nepo devohs ehS
.raef elbaton tuohtiw dias elbatsnoc eht
,rettuc eunever taht no elbatsnoc eht ekil
.gnitaeh maets ro ,sag
,retniw eht ni emoh a pu taeh ot desu eb nac detareneg taeh eht dna
tnega na fo seenk eht otni gnimmals ,niaga dellor dna denrut acceB dna
”,ercassam elbirroh a saw tI“
,desivda acceB ”,slotsip rieht fo eno tsael ta peeK“
.egamad rof etarc suoicerp os ho sih gnikcehc ylsuoixna
.ylteiuq deteerg eh
”,rotareneg cinavlag a si tI“
,lehctas sih gnihctulc llits
,sdlrow rehto no ,nexof ekil elpoep ro ,nexof rehto era ereht fi
,seriw revo yticirtcele yb derewop ,niart a fo sleehW“
,suoicsnocnu saw no dednal d’ehs selbatsnoc eht fo enO
”.ew sa emas eht selbuort evah yeht fi dna
,dnuow ylleb peed eht gnola gnicra skraps ,edalb reh htiw hguorht mih nar ehs dna
”.yrassecen ti smeed sseddoG rehtoM eht fi
,deddon elbatsnoc ehT
.sessalg dleif fo riap a revo gnidnah ,acceB dlot ehs
”.sevil ruo htiw epacse ot ykcul erew eW
.yawhctah eht morf dellac eciov a ”!retsamdrowS“
trop trawreG eht ni devirra roliaskcalB acceB retsamdrowS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,yaD ecyoR yb
.snoehcnurt rieht htiw selbatsnoc eht dna
,erutuf eht ni evah thgim ti ytilitu revetahW
.yldas dias reffaG-dnoM
.hself deziretuac fo llems eht htiw ria eht gnillif
.noitcafsitas ni deddon elbatsnoc ehT .deilper acceB
.srepap derettacs sih gnitcelloc trats ot nwod deleenk eh sa deilper reffaG-dnoM
.tset tsal eht morf egrahc tnacifingis a evah llits dluohs seirettab eht tub ,syad lareves neeb sah tI“
fo owT traP si yrots s’yadoT dna
.deddon ralohcs ehT
.thguoht ehs ,owt s’tahT
”.egdirb eht no reh teem uoy stseuqer niatpac ehT“
,tnempiuqe fo etarc sih yb tekcub denrutrevo na no gnittis saw ralohcs ehT
.reh hctac dna dnuora elcric ot deirt dworc elohw eht sa pu flesreh gniluah dna wap eno htiw foor sti fo egde eht gnibbarg
,snus rehto gnilcric
.erusiel rieht ta remmiksdniW draob neht dna
,ecneirepxe erom dah ehs ebyaM
”,ykcul taht eb ll’ew tbuod I“
!hcA“ .seriw eht fo eno hcuot ot tuo gnihcaer ,deksa acceB
”.noitcerid rieht ni ffins ton od ytiruceS etatS fo seson eht epoh dna
.detuohs stnega gniniamer eht fo eno ”!reh potS“ .eerhT
.llew sa sdlrow rehto no decitcarp ehs spahreP“ .mih dlot acceB
,tnega ceS etatS a fo tsehc eht otni gniylf htaehs eht gnidnes ,kcitsdrows eht no esaeler eht deppop ehS
,tneiciffe erom semoceb egarots yrettab eht nehw ,yademoS
”,esirprus fo tnemele eht dah uoy tub
,reffaG-dnoM gniticxe saw taht ygolonhcet wen siht fo laitnetop eht saw tI
,seirettab eht ot seriw eht hguorht slevart hcihw
,noitome elbaeciton tuohtiw tnar siht ot gninetsil neeb dah ohw ,elbatsnoc ehT
”?sseddoG rehtoM eht fo eman eht ni tahW“
.gnimoc eb yam raw a taht raef I .drah
”,tniop ruoy dnatsrednu I tub ,larutan yletelpmoc toN“
,dias ehs ”,sessetnuoC yrtnuoC rehtoM eht fo ecivres eht ta
”.su no esirprus a sgnirps ymene na nehw epoc ot elba eb ton thgim ew neht ,gnikniht ruo ni digir oot er’ew fI
.tnemeerga ni deddon tub
aes reh dehcuot edalb s’acceB fo talf eht sa
,ylkaelb dias reffaG-dnoM ”,oS“
,enO traP ni ylsuoiverP
,ti fo tib elttil a esU“
.no os dna ,knarc ot notsip ot enigne maets morf refsnart lacinahcem eht ni ygrene gnisol tuohtiw
,gniliar eht no denael yeht sa acceB ot dias reffaG-dnoM ”,egnartS“
”,neht sseccus ruoy rof rehtoM eht ot yarp lliw I“
,htaed s'dyeF htiw dedne sah
,kcab dekcilf srae
,gur a tsniaga sehsurb liat ruoy nehw semitemos leef uoy citats eht ekil ,egrahc lacirtcele na setareneg os gnioD
,decniw acceB .dias reffaG-dnoM
”,tnereffid tsuj ,tcefrep toN“
.niahc rellor yvaeh a yb
,ytirohtuA troP neffahneppilK eht fo mrofinu eht ni selbatsnoc nezod-flah a erew
,dyeF ,tnanetueil reh htiw gnola
,wap drows reh dexelf ehS .deilper acceB
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
”?nemyrtnuoc ruoy fo enin fo sevil eht dna
,kced eht ot tnega eht gnippord ,srae s’elam eht neewteb yltrams nwod ti thguorb dna
.setunim ytriht tuoba ni su tpecretni ll’tI“ .mih dlot acceB
.kcab dellac acceB
.drows eurt ym deveirter eh nehw nibac ym ni kcab ti tup evah dluow
snoog ceS etatS demrofinu-kcalb ruof eht pleh ot detfard ylsuoivbo
.denialpxe reffaG-dnoM
.niap fo llab latef a otni pu delruc dna gninaorg dnoces eht
,dekohc eh ”!tkcürrev ud tsiB“
.tcaer dluoc ew erofeb stnega ceS etatS eht lla nwod dennug lessev ymene eht no sretoohsprahS“
.werc s'rethgierf eht dna
,meht dniheb deppord dna ,hgih dleh edalb
,emit siht selfir yklub ton ,slotsip htiw demra stnega ceS etatS ruof eht
,etunim a rof ti htiw elggurts mih gnihctaw retfA
”.setunim evif-ytrof spahreP“
.deksa niatpac eht ”?retsamdrows A“ .wob
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.tekcajefil a mih evig ew retfa ralohcs eitraw‘ denmad taht ot emas eht od neht
dnE ehT   .deerga acceB
,secnatsid gnol rof strac rewop neve thgim ti
.etarc sti ni rotareneg eht ot yllacinori derutseg ehS
.deticxe erom gniworg ,demialcxe reffaG-dnoM ”!sey
.yas uoy sa ,digir oot gniworg si ti spahrep ,yrtnuoc yM“
”!gninthgil yb kcurts gnieb ekiL !kcohs ereves a nettog evah dluoc uoY
”,tih dluow ti erehw wonk t’ndluow uoY
.flesreh kcohs dna dednuorg yllatnedicca eb t’ndluow ehs os
.aes nepo eht fo ytefas eht ot
.doolb s’dyeF htiw nworb gninrut ruf eht
sdraob nedoow eht kcab leep ot swap sih morf ti koot dna dehgis acceB
,reh hsur ot deirt ohw elbatsnoc a edisa dettaws acceB
,enibrut maets a yb derewop ylbaborp ,rettuc eunever llams a gnittops ,seye reh ot meht desiar acceB
tahw wonk I“ .elzzum reh debbur niatpac ehT
,evol ,hgual htob eW“
.noitamrofni timsnart ,semoh taeh
,werc s’remmiksdniW fo eno ees ot denrut acceB
”.rolias on er’uoY“
.noitpartnoc eht morf yawa wap reh gnippals ,tuo deirc reffaG-dnoM ”!ti hcuot ton oD
”.steerts eht ni edolpxe thgim taht senigne maets suoregnad deen regnol on yeht os
.acceB tsniaga gnillaf dna eerf gnitsiwt ,detuohs eh ”,kcab og t’now I !oN“
.seitraw‘ fo dworc eht otno nwod thgir
.ylprahs dias ehs
”.efas rotareneg siht peek dna ,ereh yats uoY“
”gninthgiL eht hctaC oT“ saw sihT
”!siht od tonnac uoY“
.gninthgil ekil eb deedni dluow tI
.lla ti yfitnedi ot desserp drah saw acceB taht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,seY“ ”?leehw a nruT“
,drawrof srae reh dekcoc acceB
,melborp elbakrow A
.gninrut sleehw elddap sti tpek senigne maets deleuf lohocla s’pihs eht elihw
”?meht nurtuo t’nac ew ti ekat I“
”?thgir lla eb ot gniog elpoep ym era
kcab rewol reh ot depparts ylitsah yrettab latem yvaeh eht
”.gnihcaorppa pihs a s’ereht ekil skool tI“
,reh tsap degniz tellub A
"gninthgiL eht hctaC oT"
”!ti htiw leehw a nrut nac uoy ,llits retteB
”.nwod uoy esahc ot meht htiw emoc ew dednamed dna slaitnederc sih gnivaw detrats reciffo ceS etatS taht nehw elbuort eb ot gniog saw ti wenk I“ .dias eh ”,dooG“
.stsif otni werd yeht sa sdap mlap reh otni gniggid swalc
,kcod eht no ynam taht no ekat ot elba erew tnanetueil ruoy dna uoY“
,elxa na ot dehcatta eriw reppoc eht fo skcolb lareves gnilaever ,murd eht fo edis eht denepo eH
”,werc ym fo sevil eht htrow t’nera uoY
.reffaG-dnoM no kcehc ot ylfeirb dloh ograc eht ot denruter acceB
”.liat ruo ffo meht teg ylniatrec dluow tahT .tlob
.elballortnocnu ylraen ti sekam seriw tuohtiw yticirtcele detcejorP“
.egaugnal emas eht ni deksa ehs ”?siht revo sroirepus ruoy htiw elbuort otni teg t’now uoY“
denepo hctah eht ,euc no thgiR
”,epoh ylno nac eW“
,yltneiciffe erom hcum
.tcaer dna nrut dluoc yeht erofeb selbatsnoc erom owt gninnuts
lotsip a gnitniop tnega ceS etatS gniniamer eht ees ot denrut acceB dna ,detuohs enoemos ”!tlaH“
,sniart rewop ot desu eb dluoc ti woh meht dlot
”,retsamdrows ,seY“
.lufepoh gnihtemos otni denethgirb noisserpxe sih nehT
.ni gud dah yrettab yvaeh eht fo segde eht erehw
”.kced ym revo lla gnideelb meht ekil t’nod I
latem yarg llud fo skcolb erom lareves yb dednuorrus
”.elpoep tcefrep hcus yb degduj eb ot erac ton dluow I“
,seenk sih ot nwod deppord reffaG-dnoM dna ,yltpurba mih fo og tel ehS
.reh rof detiaw niatpac eht erehw ,egdirb eht ot dna reddal eht pu dehsur acceB
.werc s’remmiksdniW eht ot pu detuohs tnega eht
ytiruceS etatS s'trawreG htiw ni nur a dna syaled tuB
,snoilleber llams ni egagne ylno nac yehT
.taorht sih ta swalc reh htiw etarc eht tsniaga mih gninnip
.retaw eht otni dna gniliar eht revo meht gnikconk
,troffe siht fo lla“
.srehto eht htiw gnola
.deilper niatpac eht
”.semit eht htiw pu peek eW“
.tnega ceS etatS eht ot derutseg ehS
.meht gnoma gnidnats
,hcraeser sih dednuf dah taht seirtsinim tnemnrevog trawreG eht deticxe osla dah dna
drows eht degnulp ehS
.raef desserppus ni tuo gnifoolf liat ,deredduhs eH
.swap reh morf gnippird doolb s’dyeF
.ylneve deilper ehs ”,ytud ym wonk I“
.ti ees ot evil d’ehs detbuod ehs
,rehtona tuo tel ehs nehT
,retawaes htiw reknub laoc reh esuod ot niatpac s’rettuc eht gnidausrep ni dedeeccus acceB
detcepsus ehs tuB
”,dniheb morf gnimoc rettuc a tog ev’eW“
.murd eht fo evruc edisni eht ot detnuom
.ylregae denialpxe ralohcs eht
”.tnereffid era trawreG dna CM eht ekiL“ .dias acceB
,efil s’dyeF tsoc ti
,eerf ti llup ot deirt ehs sa desruc neht ,seidob dekcats rieht otni peed
.deerga reffaG-dnoM
.deksa ehs ”?revo ti sI“
”,uoy draob ot fah llits lliv eW“
,krad eht ni won meht dniheb selim owt spahrep saw tI
,reh dettops tnega htruof eht nehT .xiS .eviF
lliv uoY“ .egdod ot elbanu dna
,roliaskcalB nailacceB retsamdrowS“
,ylluferac niatpac eht ta gnikool
.senigne maets gib rof deen eht gnitanimile
.ralohcs eht ta walcregnif a delggaw ehS
,raew ehs detsisni dah reffaG-dnoM
.gnipsag dna gnikohc
tsitneics eht fo rotcetorp elos eht sa acceB sevael dna
,sexob latem esoht
,dias dna doots eh
lotsip sih desiar tnega rehtona nehT
.mih erussaer ot deirt acceB ”,uoy dna
.ezis sti rof enigne gib a dna tfard rellams a sah rettuc tahT
,sselesu tsomla saw
,ytiruces rof sroolf deifirtcele dna secnef deifirtcele detnaw yeht dias yehT
hcoH lraT yb detide
.lessev regral eht ot pu hctac ot detnaw ti yletarepsed woh ta gnitnih
trawreG htiw ,ffo delias dna pihs eht draoba uoy detrocse evah dluoc ew
,nevahneppilK fo
,dnuora mih nups dna redluohs eht yb reffaG-dnoM debbarg acceB sa erehwyreve gnillips srepap ,kced eht ot deppord lehctas rehtael ehT
.nihtiw ezirp eht laever dna
,esool edalb drows reh ot yrettab eht morf gnidael seriw eht deknay acceB taht retfA
.sroirraw ton ,srolias era werc ym tub ,retsamdrows ,noissim siht no decalp ecnegilletnI fo yrtsiniM eht ecnatropmi
,swap reh desiar acceB
”!yrautcnas em desimorp uoY“ .detuohs ralohcs eht
,noitnevni suoiretsym sih fo epytotorp eht dna
”?su tpecretni yeht erofeb gnol woh ,t’nac uoy fI“
”…ot tnenoppo ruoy fo pot no thgir tsomla eb ot evah dluow uoY“ .dias reffaG-dnoM
.htob meht gniwollof niatpac eht
.seciov rieht esiar ot lufraef oot era ti tsniaga tuo kaeps thgim ohw trawreG ni elpoep ehT
daehklub eht yb kcar loot a morf gnignah rabworc a deveirter ralohcs ehT
.meht dniheb ylthgils gnidnats elbatsnoc tsal eht
.sevaw eht revo raeh ot werc s’rettuc eht rof hguone duol ,deilper niatpac eht
,robrah eht fo tuo decar remmiksdniW sa kced gniyaws eht no doots ehs elihw edisni tnanetueil reh deirrac swap lufpleH   yaD ecyoR yb ”gninthgiL eht hctaC oT“ :yojne esaelP
.nexof eht yllanif dna ,slamina sti ,stnalp sti
snoitca ruoy dluow tahw ,t’nac I fI“
,reffaG-dnoM dnuof ehs erehT
.resiw eht enon ytiruceS etatS
.eriw a gnola slangis dnes nac uoy
,knarc a saw tnenimorp tsoM
,kcab rewol gnihca reh debbur acceB
.ylsuoixna reh ot gnivaw
.mir renni eht no stengam egral eht yb detaerc dleif citengam eht hguorht gnivom era yeht
.desiar worbeye ,deksa acceB
.ruoF .mrofinu dekaos-
.tpada ot thguat era sretsamdrowS“ .deilper ehs
.pirg s’rolias eht ni yldliw gnilggurts nageb reffaG-dnoM sa
,lla ni stnatabmoc laitnetop neT
.lehctas sih otni kcab meht deffuts eh sa srepap sih hguorht gnikool ylnrolrof
,kcab sih dniheb dnuob swap s’ralohcs eht
.meht ot flesym rednerrus dluohs I spahreP“
.yltfiws dezilaer acceB
noehcnurt sih desiar
erom…erom gniworg ,sraey rof gnignahc ,gnignahc
,remmiksdniW edisgnola pu emac rettuc eunever eht sa dehctaw acceB
,ygolohtna sretsamdrowS gnimocpu 'sserP xoF deruomrA ni elbaliava eb noos lliw hcihw ,yaD ecyoR yb
,lioc a otni seriw eht parW
.tiusrup rehtruf ot tpmetta t’ndid ehs yhw ot sa esucxe elbanosaer a edivorp ot
”,raw a eb t’now ereht epoh I“
,foor tew eht gnola dils ehS
lleh kraD dna dloC  ’sseddoG rehtoM eht yb tahW
.srolias ylsuoivbo erew ohw nexof demranu ruof erew erehT .seidob gnitnuoc
,degreme seriw reppoc fo riap a
,kced s’remmiksdniW eht ot epor a pu delbmarcs ehs nehT
”,sevlesruoy rednerrus lla lliv uoy—
”?ti htiw od uoy od tahw
.sruoy fo etarc suoicerp taht eveirter ot ruoh ydoolb a tiaw su edam uoy esuaceb
won thgir ta gnikool saw ehs tahW
.evael ot dah I taht wenk I neht saw tI“
,kced dedworc a no
.werc s’rettuc eht fo pleh eht htiw edis eht revo stnega eht fo seidob eht evaeh ot detrats dna
”.ssenkrad eht ni meht esol nac dna ykcul yrev teg ew sselnu ,pu hctac ll’yehT
.etulas ni edalb gnikraps
”.taht ot emoc ti tel t’now eW“
”.truh eb ot elpoep ruoy fo yna hsiw ton did I
murd eht fo retnec eht morF
.kced eht no nwod mih dial ehs erofeb daed saw dyeF wenk ehs tub
”,roliaskcalB retsamdrowS“
”?kcits-drows taht evah llits uoy od ,retsamdrowS“
.stnega ceS etatS eht fo eerht dna
.dednamed acceB ”?od siht fo lla seod tahw tuB“
”.yab ta raw fo kaeps ohw esoht peek ot hguone eb lliw ti ,taht ees htob nac ew fi spahreP .raef dna ,yrc
,ralohcS ,deniart reve ev’I setanidrobus tseb eht fo eno tsol tsuj I“
spahrep ,taobefil a ni em stes niatpac eht fI
.thgin sselnoom eht ni gnikniw ,srats eht ta pu dekool eH
.kced gniyaws eht no gnitoof reh peek ot elba saw ehs gnimussa
flesruoy rednerrus
,draobrevo etarc detsalb taht pmuD“ ”?eb
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,sexob daerb fo ezis eht sreniatnoc dael fo seires a gnidael
,hcihw fo gnikaepS“
,kced eht ot dehsarc etarc eht fo edis ehT
elzzum sih ot nrohllub a desiar stnega ceS etatS eht fo enO
.trats eht morf ekatsim a saw sihT“
”.nwod dennug erew stnega eht woh wohs ot esuohleehw eht ni seloh emos toohs nac uoy os“
”!gniod uoy era tahW“
,taorht reh ni peed delworg acceB
trawreG ni yldlim dias elbatsnoc eht ”,sdratsab ytiruceS demrofinu-kcalb esoht dekil reveN“ .suoicsnocnu
”,yaw taht skooL“
”?ega dna yad siht nI“
.slessev ralimis ot nosirapmoc ni ylno tub
,rotareneg cinavlag ym tnemnrevog eht dewohs I
”.—ps sa detucexe dna ,deirt
.noitcepsni rof deppots erew ew fi snoicipsus gnisuora diova ot ,egayov siht rof gnola snopaew gnirb t’ndid yletarebiled eW
”.su draob ot sdnetni werc sti taht dnim ym ni tbuod on evah I
,thgin krad eht otni demaets pihs ograc eht nopuerehw
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,thguoht gniyfirret A“
,esuohleehw s’rettuc eht dniheb degdod ehs dna
.deretnuoc reffaG-dnoM ”,tnereffid oot toN“
.dlrow eritne eht tceffa dluow ti
”?retsamdrows ,rettuc taht no eb thgim sreidlos ynam woH“
”.egrahc eht erots hcihw
dniheb ti tfel tsuj d’ew fI
,kced eht otno tuo reffaG-dnoM devohs ylhguor rolias a dna
”,won elpoep ym toN“
,htaerb sih deniager d’eh nehW
”,meht rof hguone eb lliw pu em gnikcip
.ereht mih dleh acceB sa kced leets eht no esahcrup rof gnilbbarcs seot ,gniglub seye
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”.larutan yletelpmoc saw ti fi sa nopaew deifirtcele ruoy ot koot uoy teY
”?xob a ni gninthgiL“
,ylthgit kcits-drows eht fo eldnah nedoow gnitcudnoc-non eht deppirg ehS
detuohs tnega ceS etatS eht
.roliaskcalB retsamdrowS ,yrros ylurt ma I .yrros ma I“
,detalitum os gnieb taob reh fo thguoht eht ta ruos dekool niatpac ehT
.draobrevo ralohcs eht gnipmud tsuj fo noitseggus ralimis s’niatpac eht gnirebmemer
dyeF …dyeF“ .deilper ehs ”,seY“
.rethgierf yrtnuoC rehtoM gnitiaw a draoba
rednow I semitemoS“
”.esahc eht dne dna taht htiw deifsitas eb ll’yeht ,ykcul er’ew fI