,skcen rieht ta sfeihcrek dna
.dnuorg eht drawot ylluferac yrev detniop selzzum eht htiw dleh selfir rieht
,acceB drawot ti esiar ot xobreppep reh gniward
”.em gniniart erew uoy nehw saw hceeps elttil taht draeh I emit tsal ehT“
renroc a dnuora deddiks yeht sa gniralb eltsihw
.ralohcS ,enod llew saw tahT“
deton dyeF ”,doom lacihposolihp a ni er’uoY“
.etarc suoicerp eht dnuora selbac eht gniruces hsinif ot deirruh werc s’remmiksdniW eht sa ,deksa dyeF ”?warD“
,mih ydaets ot mra s’ralohcs eht debbarg dna doots dyeF
,pets elbacoverri
,nortap rieht rof noissim siht no gnola mih thguorb d’ehs yhw saw hcihW
.ffo gniog srekcarcerif fo gnirts a ekil
,meht dekcatta uoy nehW
,pihs eht morf tuohs a saw erehT
.yldetcepxenu pu ekops reffaG-dnoM ”,nac I“
,elbatsnoc dnoces ehT
.gel ”doog“ reh no ylsuoregnad gniyaws
.gniliar eht yb doots htob yeht sa
”,ti yortsed ot evah ll’eW .gib oot s’tahT“
,dnuorg eht ot pord ti gnittel dna
,llih eht nwod delttar trac maets eht sa dyeF ot detuohs acceB ”!sekarB“
.esuoheraw eht morf epytotorp eht teg ot evah eW“
.dnammoc reh ni tnanetueil elbapac a nevorp d’eh
.noegrus s’pihs eht rof demaercs ehs sa neve yltneg nwod mih gniyal
rorroh desserppus s’acceB oT
eltsihw duol a draeh ehs sa ecno reh dniheb decnalg ylno ehS
skcatsekoms rieht morf sduolc krad gnihcleb seirotcaf eht sdrawot wap drows reh htiw gnirutseg
”,retsamdrows ,eurt si sihT“
.ylbaffa deilper eh ”,stalf gnippihs fo riap a fo ezis eht tsuJ .egral yrev ton ,hO“
.temmulp rieht tuo denethgiarts dna
.sretfar eht sdrawot dellepxe gnieb slaoc gninrub eht fo sseldeeh ,edisni thgiarts ti evord yeht
.ylmlac deilper acceB
,ria eht otni etarc suoicerp s’reffaG-dnoM gnihcniw nageb enarc eht dna
.tlah a ot dehceercs trac maets eht sa meht drawot yawgnag s’pihs eht nwod emac
.daeh s’elbatsnoc eht sdrawot egde tnulb eht gnihsals
.sllaw eht no spmal lio eht morf ykoms ria eht
.kcod gnidecer eht fo noitcerid eht ni deppans daeh reh sa latem no latem fo gnaps a htiw tih gnihtemoS
.gninnirg ,deilper acceB
,ygolohtna sretsamdrowS
.eciton tcartta yldrah dluow ,meht gniwollof renwo sti htiw ,skcod eht ot teerts eht nwod knurt a gniyrrac srolias owT
.aera ograc eht dna
,sreeb ruo hsinif ot gniog lla era ew woN
dias acceB ”,draoba teg esaelp neht ,noitseuq ruoy ksA .eniF“
.eelem eht ni sedarmoc nwo rieht gnitoohs ksir ot detnaw stnega ytiruceS etatS eht fo eno sselnu
,ylmrif dias elbatsnoc eht
”?noonretfa eht ni etal siht ytic ymene na fo elddim eht ni trac maets a pu erujnoc tsuj nac I kniht uoy od yhW“ .deredro acceB
.deilper reffaG-dnoM ”,dica ciruhplus dna ,setalp dael ,stengam lairtsudni ,gniriw reppoC“
.ylniatrec ,sroirraW“
.gniht ycnaf a ton saw tI
”.ecaep ni sevil rieht evil ot hsiw ylpmis tsoM
.srepap fo lehctas suoicerp sih gnihctulc dna yaw eht fo tuo gnidnats
”.evom ot ydaer teg dna srednatsyb tneconni ruo eruces em pleH“ .deilper ehs
.enog gnol eb d’yeht ,taht ot dnuora tog werc s’trac maets eht emit eht yb tub
.ralohcs eht ot denrut ehs ,pihs eht otno pu nar tnanetueil reh sA .deredro acceB
.noitavargga ni thguoht acceB ,lla su sselb sseddoG rehtoM
”,mih htiw ton eW .won ere‘“
”!tey toN .on ,hO“ ”?dootsrednu
.yaw eht fo tuo gnippets dnoyeb ti fo eciton elttil ekat ot demees dworc ehT
yralubatsnoc lacol eht erofeb setunim net spahrep evah ew kniht I
.leets reh tsniaga ekorb ti sa kcarc ytsan dnoces a draeh ehs dna
ti revo gnah ot ylwols gnitovip enarc ograc s’pihs eht
.ni gud dah sdap ekarb eht erehw gnikoms sleehw nedoow s’trac eht fo sbuh eht
deredro acceB ”,dloH“
.edalb sti revoc dna htaehs s’enac eht barg ot nwod gnileenk ,dednamed ehs
,mra dednuow gnihctulc
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”,redrum detpecca-tnemnrevog
,edalb eht nups ehS
,klawedis eht fo egde eht revo decnuob dna
,gnihcaorppa erew yralubatsnoc lacol eht fo mrofinu eht ni sreciffo ruoF
.meht evoba dezzihw
ytic eht detisiv taht srolias eht htob ot deretac taht spohs rehto dna ,srettiftuo ,sknab ,srab fo enil eht gniwollof
.ekalgnoL ssetnuoC
,gnimmar ta troffe denimreted a htiw dloh t’ndluow tI
ffo tsac ot ydaer edam werc s’pihs eht sesruc dna stuohs htiW
”.noisseforp ruoy ekil ton od uoy fi sa dnuos uoY“
.gnineve siht emoh emoc ot meht gnitcepxe era ohw seilimaf evah yehT
.hcneb s’revird eht otno pu deppoh acceB
.thguoht ehs ,tihs ot yletelpmoc enog sah siht lleW
.yruf ni gnihsal liat sih
,peed a koot acceB
,rae reh dekcin tellub a sa ylfeirb reh gninefaed ,tuo gnar tohs A
.noitan rieht tsniaga gnitca seips ymene
.eciohc citsitra ton
.eciffo s’rosivrepus esuoheraw eht drawot puorg eht gnidreh detrats ehs
.enac nedoow ,kciht a ot thgit dleh acceB dna
.mlap nwo reh ni pu ti gnikat
.etarc eht ot selbac eht fo tsal eht gniruces dehsinif yllanif dah srolias eht erehw
”!dyeF ,kraD dna dloC“
.edis s’reffaG-dnoM ot esolc yats ot dyeF rof noitom dna
.placs sih ot gninettalf srae ralugnairt
”,stiftuo tnerruc ruo htiw tif yldrah dluow tI“
”.uoy fo noitseuq a ksa ot hsiw tsrif I“
kcuts flesreh gnidnif rolias a rof elbatius
”?draoba teg esaelp uoy dluow woN“ .pihs eht drawot derutseg ehS
.sredro tuohs ot gniunitnoc ,yawgnag eht pu kcab nar ehS
.rednerrus ni smra rieht desiar neht dna rehto hcae htiw skool feirb degnahcxe ohw
.dnuorg eht ot gnilbmut mih gnidnes dna
,drows s’acceB gniyrrap ylfeirb bulc retrohs eht
.taorht sih ta sevink s’dyeF fo eno htiw
,elam nexof elgnis a yb deipucco elbat llams a
,daptoof eno no yltrams denrut dna
.dnuorg eht ot tsrif tuons llef ehs dna ,ti werdhtiw eH
,reh ta noehcnurt sih devaw eH
yrotirret yrtnuoC rehtoM otni gnissorc
,ti dehcaer yeht emit eht yB
”,nwod eciov denmad ruoy peeK“
,despalloc eh sa mih debbarg acceB ”…dluohs ew ,seY“
syar s’nus gnirewol eht sa roloc egnaro tnrub a gninrut saw yks eht
,elzzum sih ot deppilc zen ecnip a gniraew dna ruf der peed htiw
.dedepminu teerts eht nwod lerrab ot dewolla saw ti dna
.latner yrevil tseraen eht ot snoitcerid teg ot kloferohsgnol ybraen a nwod gniggalf
,nexiv derruf-kcalb A
.tdatsnesiE ni ecnerefnoc a gnidnetta m’I
.htiw tnemugra on evah I elpoep sti—
”!pihs eht ekaT“ .trawreG ni detuohs reciffo eht ”!meht potS“
”.ecnerefnoc eht ot fo daetsni ereh deppihs yllatnedicca saw ti retfa epytotorp ym gniveirter ylerem ma I !suoegartuo oS …os gnihtyna fo draeh reven evah I-
,niaga deksa dyeF ”?warD“
”,elzzum ruoy ot pu taht dloh t’noD“
.ediw sa flah dna gnol smra evif
.dednuow yleros ro daed
.lavirra ym rof daeha ereh deppihs ti dah I oS“
,eciffo s’rosivrepus eht otni enoyreve gnidreh dehsinif yeht rehtegoT
.draug lanosrep s’ekalgnoL ssetnuoC fo smrofinu thgirb eht ton
?uoy htiw meht gniyrrac dna selbatsnoc eht pu gnikcip fo rovaf taerg eht em od dluoc uoy fi woN
.delaever saw ti edisni neddih drows eht sa
,dnuorg eht no enac eht tes ot revo denael ehS
.esuoheraw eht ta su pots ot deirt ohw selbatsnoc ehT“
.ytisoiruc ni reh sdrawot srae sih dekcoc reffaG-dnoM ”.os erom spahrep
.dezilaer ehs ,pihs eht ot kcab ti luah ot trac maets a deen d’yeht naem dluow hcihW
”,snoitacilpmoc erew erehT“ .dednamed ehs
,tnemssarrabme ni kcab dekcilf srae s’dyeF
?swolb gnillik ekirts ot tnedurp erom neeb evah ton ti dluoW
,strihs nenil yvaeh
.eltsihw eht dednuos yldetaeper acceB sa
,tih htaehs eht sa kcarc prahs a draeh ehS
”!mlehliW“ .maercs dehctip-hgih a htiw kcod eht fo egde eht ffo gnilbmut
,swonk yrtsiniM ecneicS eht sa raf sA“ .dias reffaG-dnoM
,sraey ytriht nwo s’acceB naht regnuoy sraey thgie saw elam derruf-ydnas ehT
,suoregnad taht gnihtemos wolla reven dluow ssetnuoc yrtnuoC rehtoM A
,ruf kcalb reh gnitaroced selkceps yarg htiw nexiv dega na
.ylmrif detaeper acceB ”,dloH“
.yllacitegolopa dettimda dyeF
.mra sih rednu ylthgit dleh srepap fo lehctas sih
,sdraknat eht gnibbarG
,yltpurba pu tuhs ehS
.niaga ecno taorht sih dnuora ylesool tser ot elzzum sih morf nwod kcab feihcrek eht dellup eh dna
,swap dna smra sih fo ruf eht gnittod snrub lacimehc morf stops etihw llams erew ereht dna
”.ni dekrow eh yrotcaf eht ta sreliob laoc eht htiw rehtaf ym depleh I“
”?siz yas ot uoy era ohW“
”.demrah eb ton lliw uoy dna ,yllufecaep evael ot su wolla woN“
,krelc esuoheraw eht htiw noitaitogen feirb a retfA
.ylkciuq dias reffaG-dnoM ”,on ,oN“
don mrif a evag reffaG-dnoM nehT
.etag niam eht sdrawot noitommoc gniworg a ot nward saw noitnetta rieht neht tub
su htiw klaw dexaler ,ecin a ekat ot gniog er’uoy neht dna
.tius dewollof dyeF retal tnemom a dna
,stleb rieht ta sevink nairatilitu gnol erow htob
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,drawrof dehsur ehS
,enigne maets s’trac eht ot detcennoc hcniw a yb dedia ksat a
.tleb reh morf gnignah gnir a hguorht edalb eht dehtaehs ehS ”…hguoht ,drows A
.ecnaraeppa nommoc ylluferac rieht gninimaxe
”?epytotorp tahW ?epytotorP“
”.neffahneppilK rof tekcit niart eht esahcrup stneduts ym fo eno dah neve I
.tsehc s’dyeF ni seloh ydoolb owt eht ta gnirats
.pihsnezitic trawreG sih gnitufer dna
,stnap savnac hguot ni
.tnanetueil reh sdrawot gninrut ,desruc ehs
…hcihw fo gnikaepS
lortnoc deniager ehs erofeb llats s’relles tiurf a hguorht gnihsams
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.desuorg acceB ”,thgir lla ,thgir llA“ .deredro elbatsnoc eht ”,esaelp ,llew sa enac ruoY“
,sregnif reh neewteb lriwt latnemirepxe na ti evag ehS
.mih dlot acceB ”,draoba teg dluohs uoy ,reffaG-dnoM ralohcS“
trac maets dedaolrevo na sa klawedis dedworc eht otno dna
,tleb reh ta lotsip xobreppep a dna redluohs thgir reh morf gnignah diarb dlog eht yb reciffo na
dluoc yeht dna pihs gnitiaw eht draoba tellap eht daol si
.suoicsnocnu roolf eht ot mih gnikconk
.deirrow sa neeb evah t’ndluow ehs
.smlap denrutpu sih no gnitser edalb dekan eht
”.deredrum neeb sah esuops rieht swen eht eviecer dna
:ytic trop lairtsudni trawreG lacipyt a saw neffahneppilK .elam nexof regnuoy eht emalb dluoc nexiv eht taht toN
.ylevitcetorp lehctas eht dettap eH
”,tnemom eht ta ot em tnaw dluow uoy naht erom tol a tuo gnidnats eb d’I ,did I fI“
,denrut ehs noitom htooms eno ni neht
.robrah eht otni tuo gnittuj sevrahw eht ot
.tcirtsid siht ni sesuoheraw eht dednet ohw srekrow eht dna
.trawreG ni deksa ehs ”?ereh tis ew fi dniM“
.htob meht rof sreeb desahcrup dna rednetrab eht nwod deggalf ehS
.dnuorgkcab eurt sih ta gnitnih
,trac maets eht dna sreidlos eht neewteb
.llik ot deraperp eb I taht seriuqer ecivres taht dna
,niap ni revo delbuod eh sA
.deredro acceB ”!llor dna warD“
smra derdnuh rehtona dils yehT
”...llits saw ehs fi ees ot dekcehc evah dluohs eW“
,rallip a tsniaga dennip dna demrasid saw htruof eht elihw
.ecalp ni rab gnikcol eht gnittes
”!krow s’efil ym si tI
”.daetsni ecnerefnoc eht ot ti gnidnes saw I rollecnahc ytisrevinu eht dlot I
”!reffaG-dnoM ralohcS
,tnrub fi sa yrc duol a tuo tel ehs dna ,dap wap reh no taeh fo hsalf a tlef ehS
.evlav a pu denepo dna
.tcirtsid esuoheraw eht sdrawot
,deddon reffaG-dnoM
,dyeF ot detuohs acceB ”!ylno stalF“
elkna s’wollef roop eht gnikaerb
nrevat llams a dehcaer yeht litnu stnorferots gnitnuoc
.deilper eh ”,seY“ .deksa ehs
”,esaelp kcod eht fo edis eht revo selfiR“
,demialcxe reffaG-dnoM
,snopaew ytilauq-retsamdrows lla htiw sa
snoehcnurt htiw demra sreciffo eciloP
.edis eno ot nael mih edam
.pirg sih fo eerf noehcnurt eht deppilf dna wap reh ni edalb eht detovip ehs litnu
stnetnoc ythgiew s’lehctas eht sa ecnalab sih gnisol tsomla ,pu doots dna deddon
,ecalp fo tuo eb yletinifed dluow sdrowS
feihcsim fo tuo dna deipucco swap s’werc eht htiW
,spop fo seires duol a daeh acceB
”.pihs eht ot kcab etarc sih gnirb tsuj ot dlot erew eW“
,nwod dna pu detrad seye siH
ta tohs eb ot esolc oot ,sreidlos dalc kcalb fo kcap eht fo elddim eht ni
fo eno trap saw sihT
hcoH lraT yb detide
.deilper eh ”,sdneirf rof…rof gnitiaw ma I
.edalb reh fo lemmop eht htiw ecaf eht ni retoohs eht gnikirts ,detovip ehs dna
,nepo meht dehsup dna rood eht ot revo deirruh dyeF
deddon eH .tuo dellac ehs
thguoht I .sevisolpxe retteb dna reggib gnikam tuoba erac ylno ohw
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tnetni htiw ti ward I nehW .llik ot
,detrats dah thgif eht ecnis reve teiuq neeb d’eH
tcirtsid esuoheraw eht morf yawliar ralucinuf refas tub evisnepxe erom a dliub daetsni dluow tub
.ylthgils gnitnap ,denruter dyeF
,skcod eht ot nur peets yrev dna
”,stoidi ot boj ym nialpxe ot evah I nehw yaw taht teg I“
.epols peets eht nwod tnew ti sa gnisruc namekarb eht
,moor eht fo kcab eht drawot yllausac dyeF dediug ehs
”.uoy demlehwrevo evah thgim yeht esiwrehtO
selbatsnoc demrofinu nezod a tsael ta fo xnalahp a was dna
,detacude ylsuoivbo saw tnecca sih tub ,brag renommoc ni desserd saw eH
”,tnemom eno ni lliw I“
,ti ni erusaelp on ekat I tuB
”?reliob eht krow ot woh wonk uoy od ,dyeF“
.dekcod saw remmiksdniW eht erehw reip eht sdrawot gninrut ,etag kcod eht hguorht trac maets eht dediug ehS .ssergorP
”gninthgiL eht hctaC oT“
.eugnoT rehtoM eht ni meht ta detuohs
,enac reh fo eldnah eht no nottub a desserp acceB nehw saw hcihW
:rof gnikool saw ehs tahw dnuof ehs yllaniF
.doolb nwo reh fo loop eht otni kcab despalloc ehs erofeb
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,yaD ecyoR yb
.ylteews desivda acceB
”?ereh deppihs ti dah uoy nehw tsefinam eht no tup uoy did tahW“
.daeh sih koohs eH
.werc eht ta enac drows reh delggaw ehS
,retal ruoh nA .derettum ehs
I“ .derettuts reffaG-dnoM ”?tahw-
.elbatsnoc dael eht drawot drows eht pu gnignirb
,srolias yrtnuoC rehtoM sa desserd htob erew yehT
.eotpilC naidyeF ,tnanetueil ym si siht dna
,revel ekarb eht no drah kcab dellup dyeF
.yldeirrow dniheb gniliart reganam esuoheraw eht
.pal sih ni gnitser srepap htiw deffuts lehctas rehtael a
,selbatsnoc suoicsnocnu eht gniyrrac
,mraerof sih htiw ti yrrap ot deirt eh ,gnikcinaP
”.neffahneppliK ot niart eht no tog I erofeb tsuj flesym tdatsnesiE rof tekcit eht thguob I
,trac maets ograc egral a fo draob gninnur eht no gnignah
,daeh sih fo kcab eht no nwod yltrams enac drows eht fo eldnah eht thguorb ehs
s’dyeF .nopaew a ylno si tI .nopaew a s’tI“
”,evirra stnemecrofnier erofeb tseb ta setunim eerht ro owt evah ew snaem hcihW“
.elbadnatsrednu ylerab dna nekorb saw tnecca reh erus gnikam ,trawreG ni dias ehs
,dedda eh tnemom a retfA .deilper dyeF
,llih eht fo pot eht ta noitcesretni na ta denrut yehT          .ssergorP
,on ,yrros ma I“
.trawreG ni derewsna acceB
,snoitan gnirafaes lareves morf srekrow dna srolias htiw dedworc saw taht moor nommoc a delaever edisni gnippetS
.srenroc ruof eht ot selbac dehcatta ot meht wolla dna
.raef elttil a spahrep dna ,tcepser erom tib a htiw tnanetueil reh dna acceB ta gnikool erew sreidlos reh fo emos
”?no gniog s’tahw ,retsamdrowS“
,ylleb s’reciffo eht morf degreme edalb s’dyeF nehw saw tahT
.rof desu eb dluoc smeti fo noitanibmoc errazib a hcus tahw derednow acceB elihw
,skcod eht sdrawot daor eht nwod deffup
.tuo dellac elbatsnoc dael eht
.nrecnoc ni deksa dyeF
”!tnereffid eb dluow CM eht
ecnatsid eht esolc ot retsamdrows eht rof raf oot
”.su htiw emoc dna sevlesruoy mrasid woN“ .pih sih ta noehcnurt eht ot pord wap sih gnittel
”!maets lluf ot sreliob eht pu gnirb ,walctoH .rM“
”.tnellecxe ,ti s’tahT
feihcrek kcen sih htiw drows sih gninaelc
,seenk sih dnuora ylsuovren delruc liat siH
secap evif yreve gnizeens morf flesreh peek ylerab dluoc acceB neve tub ,ti fo eciton on ekat ot demees
eciffo s’reganam esuoheraw eht fo noitcerid eht morf noitommoc A
.esuoheraw ybraen a drawot dna teerts eht otni tuo kcab dedaeh meht fo eerht eht rehtegot dna
gnimocpu 'sserP xoF deruomrA ni elbaliava eb noos lliw hcihw ,yaD ecyoR yb
.tnua ym rof saw ti meht dlot I“
.gurhs a htiw deilper reffaG-dnoM
.hcneb eht no reh ediseb eruces ot acceB ot lehctas sih revo gnidnah
”,roliaskcalB nailacceB retsamdrowS“
trac eht fo lortnoc tsol namekarb dna revird eht fi rucco dluow taht eganrac eht enigami ot deirt acceB
.taorht s’elam a ro ,taem tuc ot desu eb nac efink
”,su eb dluow tahT“
”,ffuts siht ni gnihtaerb morf evarg ylrae na ni sevlesmeht yrub ll’yehT“
,deeps pu dekcip trac eht dna
.rocnar tuohtiw deilper acceB ”,yfilauq t’nod
.ecneitapmi delaecnoc-lli htiw
retsaf degguhc snotsip s’reliob ehT
.slerrab ruof lla erif dluoc trawreG eht erofeb
,dyeF“ .dias ehs ”,uoy knahT“
llih peets eht drawot dedaeh yeht sa
.doog yrev s’tahT ?esaelp trac eht morf nwod emoc lla uoy dluoc ,uoy knahT“
,rennam tnatiseh sih etipseD
.ytiruceS etatS fo yrtsiniM dedaerd s’trawreG fo smrofinu kcalb eht ni
.setunim net naht ssel ni
denrut eH ”.retsamdrows ,seY“
.tnegru gniworg enot sih
.elbissop revenehw ti diova lliw dna
.nepo deppord waj s’dyeF ,reh ediseB
”.ni era yeht noitarugifnoc tahw noitnem ot deliaf tsuj I .tcerroc lla si tI“
?dam uoy era ,ti yortseD“ .mih dlot acceB
”,uoy knaht ,citanul suoredrum delliks s’tahT“
”.ytic siht ni ecnerrucco nommocnu na ton si tI“
”.stsiruot ekil kool ll’eW“ .desivda acceB
,gniniamer sreidlos demra tub detrecnocsid yrev eerht tfel taht dna ,reciffo eht dna ruof fo latot reh ddA
)2 fo 1 trap( yaD ecyoR yb
”gninthgiL eht hctaC oT“  :yojne esaelP
.retaw ot nigeb seye reh tlef acceB dna
.sedalb sih fo stalf eht esu ot noinapmoc ruoy deredro uoy
.yltnegru deksa dyeF ”?acceB“
:si ti tahw tub gnihtyna si ti dneterp ton od I“
edalb reh werdhtiw ehs sa elzzum eht ni reidlos dnoces a gnihsams woble tfel reh
,daeh sih koohs dyeF
,reidlos a fo ylleb eht otni degnulp edalb s’acceB
,gnihtaerb tub suoicsnocnu saw elbatsnoc driht eht taht dnif ot
.gnileef saw acceB taht
,detats ehs reciffo eht oT
.draobngis sti no resahc ssarg gnilrans a htiw dekram
.skcod eht ot gnidael
,reciffo ytiruceS etatS eht ees dluoc ehs
dyeF dna acceB hguoht
”—sid eht desolc ew retfa ecnahc a evah yllaer t’ndid swollef rooP“
.flesreh ydaets ot fi sa trac maets eht fo edis eht ot tuo gnihcaer wap reh
.suovren gnikool dna enola gnittis
.tops thgir eht ni dednal kraps a fi
:esoprup eno ylno saH“
,niatpac s’remmiksdniW
.seirotcaf ybraen eht morf tsud laoc fo kaolc kcalb a htiw derevoc dna ,dedworc ,ysub
”,selbatsnoc eht fo flah ym htiw gnilaed saw I elihw derepracs eH .on ,yrroS“
”.slleb mrala s’ydobemos ffo tes ot gniog si
bac s’revird eht neewteb detnuom
”?ralohcS ,siht ees uoy oD“ .ria sa thgil sa
,ssecorp gnirutcafunam eht fo tcafitra na saw taht wenk ehs tub ,retaw gniwolf fo taht delbmeser edalb eht nopu nrettap ehT
”.now tsuj ew kniht I“ .dennirg acceB
.dnuora dekool acceB .dias eh
”?gniog yllaer erew uoy erehw swonk nosrep eno tsael ta oS“
,dias ehs ”,dyeF ,uoy knahT“
”!ralohcS ,maets eroM“
.deb ograc eht fo tnorf eht otni gnimmals etarc derucesnu eht
.rae reh otni yletarepsed derepsihw dyeF ”?eh si erehW“
.kcab skcolb eerht tuoba morf meht drawot gnihsur
.tnew ti erehw gniwohs krowrepap eb ot gniog s’ereht dnA
yaw eht fo tuo teerts eht no dworc eht teg ot eltsihw eht welb acceB
,trac maets eht fo sleehw eht fo eno tsniaga depmuls gniyl
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.ti ot su ekat tsuJ .tuo gnihtemos erugif ll’ew
,nrettap hctah-ssorc elpmis a saw ti nopu ngised eht tub
.ylprahs mih ta kcab dekool acceB
meht fo tnorf ni evaw a ekil gnitrap dworc eht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,redro s’acceB tA
,deilper ehs ”,llih eht nwod edils taht rof su spots eno on epoh tsuj I“
,CM eht ot egayov aes ylevol a trats ot skcod eht nwod
”.guht demra na dna flesym neewteb ecnereffid ylno eht si tahT
.dloh ograc eht otni etarc eht gnirewol dehsinif enarc sti sa neve ,robrah eht fo tuo dedaeh ti
.elbat ytpme na rof gnikool fi sa
”.tnedifnocrevo era uoy kniht I“
teerts eht pu deklaw yeht sa
"gninthgiL eht hctaC oT"
,trac maets eht fo werc eht ot noitnetta reh denrut acceB
”.kniht I ,sdnuop derdnuh-neves naht erom oN“ .reh dlot eh ”,stnenopmoc tseivaeh eht era stengam eht dna setalp dael ehT“ .ralohcs eht deksa acceB ”?hgiew gniht siht seod hcum woH“
,dnuorg eht no yal sreidlos rehto eviF
.dednamed reciffo eht
.ni elpmet s’enoemos hsab ro ,tiag s’nexiv dlo na esae dluoc erofeb deirrac I enac ehT
,wap tfel reh htiw revo dehcaer acceB
,ecap gniklaw ksirb a ot nwod meht wols ot deganam dyeF
.teerts eht otno drawrof delbmur trac maets eht dna sevlav denepo reffaG-dnoM sa niaga draob gninnur eht otno gnippoh
,noitan trawreG ez ot rotiart a gnidia rof
.sbuc dna ,snexiv ,selam htiw dellif steerts gnineve ylrae eht
”.gniht elpmis a hcus smees tI“
.deilper elam eht ”,seY“
,dias acceB ”,trawreG s’tI“
.reh hctac ot fi sa drawrof dehsur
”.ytip tuohtiw seimene rieht nwod tuc ohw ,sroirraw emosraef era sretsamdrows yrtnuoC rehtoM taht dlot neeb evah I
,roliaskcalB nailacceB retsamdrowS ma I“
”,noitseuq nwo ruoy rewsna uoy nehT“
,yawgnag eht pu dedaeh dna
”.ti tuohtiw evael tonnac yletulosba eW
retaw eht gninruhc lluh eht fo edis rehtie eht no sleehwelddap taerg eht
”?taht derreferp evah uoy dluoW“
”.seton hcraeser ym tuohtiw neve
.ti htiw gnola deirrac erew yeht sa meht otno gnignah selbac eht dehcatta d’ohw srolias eht
.elims a htiw derewsna acceB
,mih sselb sseddoG rehtoM
.ylthgils xaler flesreh tlef acceB
,ngised yrtnuoC rehtoM a ekil enigne deleuf-lohocla na neeb d’ti fI
sevlesmeht tpek dyeF dna acceB
,krow ym etacilpud dna ti enimaxe dluoc esle enoemos naem dluow taht
.llew sa od ot dyeF rof gninoitom dna nwod gnittis ,deilper acceB
.uoy sa emas eht ,esiugsid ni m’I“
”,pihs eht ot kcab epytotorp s’ralohcS rreH luah ot esu nac ew trac maets a dnif ,dyeF“
,ylpeed gniwob ,dias eh ”,drows ruoY“
,ruf etihw dna kcalb nwo reh ta gnibbur trats ot egru eht thguof ehS
”.retsamdrows a ekil kool t’nod uoY“
.ralohcS ,etsaC yratiliM ma I“ .deilper acceB
”?reffaG-dnoM ralohcS era uoY .sessetnuoC fo
.enac reh no denael dna htaerb gnimlac
teerts eht fo tuo degdod yehT
;pihs siht draoba trawreG fo snezitic on era erehT“
.ylhsipeehs dettimda eh
”,lla su sselb sseddoG rehtoM“
htuoy sih etipsed tub
”.tuons ruoy ni tsud eht tpecxe gnihtyna llems t’nac uoY“ .deksa eh
decalpsim gnieb meht fo htoB
,yrtsiniM raW eht ni stoidi esoht ekil tsuj era uoy ,hO“
”,em liaf naht eid rehtar d’uoy dna ,tnanetueil ym era uoy esuaceB“ .deksa eh
mees ti gnikam ecnalab luferac eht
thgil s’yad eht fo tsal eht nI
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,detuohs reciffo eht
.lias tes ot ydaer ekam dna draoba etarc siht ekat
,remmiksdniW eht fo kced eht no erew yeht tnemom ehT
.nwot fo egde eht no
,stnenoppo erom rof moor eht dennacs ehS
.mmH“ .esirprus ni deknilb reffaG-dnoM
enac reh fo dloh mrif ekat acceB edam
”!citanul yrtnuoC rehtoM suoredrum uoy ,eiD“
,dias eh ”,dniheb tiusrup tfel ew tsael ta ,lleW“
,dezeens dyeF reh ediseB
.ytic eht revo gnignah duolc ekoms lauteprep eht tih
,dias dyeF ”,dab toN“
.draveluob niam eht otno dna
.kcab derepsihw acceB ”,ecneitaP“
,derettum dyeF ”,etuC“
.detseggus eman sih sa deye-yrrats os etiuq t’nsaw reffaG-dnoM
reliob laoc gniffup eht gnidnet reenigne dna ,namekarb ,revird htiw etelpmoc
.noitacilpmoc detcepxenu na ni
,sdrows rieht werd dna ylsuoenatlumis teef rieht ot emac yehT
,gnikniht kciuq sih dualppa ot ton deirt acceB
”,os eveileb t’nod I …I“
.swap sih ni dehtaehsnu sevink rieht fo htob htiw teef sih ot pu kcab gnimoc ,dellor dna dnuorg eht ot evod eh sa
”?tdatsnesiE ni detcepxe era uoy dna ti nehw
.demialcxe reffaG-dnoM
rood eht rewsna ot evah efiw ro dnabsuh roop emos evah naht sedalb ruo fo stalf eht esu ot retteB
,yrtnuoC rehtoM eht morf egayov eht no deziromem d’ehs nwot eht fo pam eht deweiver acceB
htaehs efink reh fo elkcub eht gniodnu yldrawkwa
.dehcaorppa yeht sa deksa acceB
”,ereh kcab meht gnirb dna sedalb reporp ruo barg ,dyeF“
,pu demaets subinmo na sa
”?lla ta dewollof uoy ereW
,etarc eht ot nwod kcab nar ylbmin srolias fo maet a sa
,tsal siht gnikat fo modsiw eht gnirednop fi sa ,knalpgnag eht pu dekool dna
”,neht gniog su teG“
.eugnoT rehtoM eht ni desivda ehs ”,dael ym wolloF“
reffaG-dnoM ralohcS
”.yrtnuoC rehtoM eht fo stcejbus devoleb ylno
.yaw yrrem rieht no eb
,thgir llA“ .dessih acceB
,siht ot timda lliw I dna ,tserra ot gnimoc snexiv dna selam erew selbatsnoc esohT“ .dias acceB
.yltnatsid derewsna dyeF ”,seY“
,deb ograc eht otni tellap eht gnitteg fo rettam a tsuj saw ti taht retfA .ssergorP
,krowrepap thgir eht rof lehctas sih hguorht gud reffaG-dnoM elihw yaled gnineddam a gnivlovni
”.flesruoy rof tops efas a dnif dna draoba niatpac eht wollof yldnik
.skcod eht fo etag tnorf eht drawot meht gnidiug
ahw-ahW“ ”.ytiruceS etatS fo yrtsiniM eht fo redro eht ta ,tserra rednu era snoinapmoc ruoy dna uoY“
;ytisrevinu eht ta ti evael tsuj t’ndluoc I“ .dias eh
,dyeF fo nruter eht dedlareh esuoheraw eht edistuo morf esion gniffup peed a
,sdrow s’reciffo eht etipseD
,sdrawkcab dereggats eH
.pirg reh evorpmi ot ereht tsuj
,flesym sa sseddoG rehtoM eht fo seye eht ni devoleb sa enoemoS
”.’ssergorP‘ deralced s’ti sa gnol os gnihtyna htiw pu tup ll’yehT“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,srehto evres ot nrob saw I snaem tahT
,gel s’elbatsnoc dnoces eht otni yltcerid htaehs dedaol gnirps ,yvaeh eht gnidnes
”.srood eht nepo ,dyeF“ .deredro acceB
.desruc niatpac eht ”,kraD dna dloC“
.mlauq a tuohtiw meht llik ll’I ,tnetni lahtel htiw em retfa semoc enoemos fI
esaelP“ .dias acceB
,kcab dennirg dyeF
”.flesym dekan ytterp gnileef m’I timda ll’I hguohT“ .deton acceB
”,rotareneg cinavlag eht fo epytotorp ehT“ .dednamed acceB
.esae nrecnoc reh fo emos tlef acceB
.knurt a fo ezis eht gnihtemos saw ti gnipoh saw ehS
.deeps gniyfitarg htiw deilpmoc yehT
.acceB ot denrut eH
deliathsif trac eht fo dne kcab ehT
,ylduol welb eltsihw sti
feiler laciretsyh deniartsnoc ylerab emas eht ni gnihgual
.kcab reh otni pit sti demmar eh sa
,rednerrus dnu sevlesruoy mrasid lliv uoY !tlaH“
”?reffaG-dnoM ralohcS“
.tuo nettalf ot nageb yllanif teerts eht neht dna
tpmetnoc ni sredael s’noitan ym dloh I
,thgiarts a saw tI
draoba ti deluah hcihw
”?ereh ti dnats yeht nac woH“
od ot evah d’yeht lla ,enoyna revo gninnur tuohtiw nwot eht hguorht dna llih eht nwod trac detsalb siht teg dluoc yeht fI
.tsol tib a gnieb mih fo esac a eb tsuj thgim gnissim gniog ereh ralohcs eht ,retsamdrowS“
.nemyrtnuoc ym era yehT“
.dniheb sreidlos eht gnivael ,yawgnag eht pu reh dewollof dna deddon dyeF ”.og ew ffo
selfir ’sreidlos eht morf stellub sa gnillor dna gnikcut ,drawrof depael dyeF dna ehs eno sA
”,ceS etatS yb tuo detros eb lliw tahT“
.noonretfa eht naht erom rof nepo eht ni tuo deyats yeht fi yerg dna kcalb noos eb dluow hcihw
reh dnuora seitraw‘ ehT
,ecnayonna ot mrala morf nekcals noisserpxe reh tel ehs sa neve
.ylesolc reh ta gnikool ,deilper ralohcs eht
,acceB sa llat sa etarc egral a erofeb thguorb erew yeht dna
”?tnew rosivrepus esuoheraw eht yaw hcihw ees uoy did ,dyeF“
”.drows ym dah I hsiw I“
.driht a fo taorht eht dehsals dna
”?reffaG-dnoM ralohcS ,epytotorp siht si egral woH“
,senotselbboc eht ssorca deddiks ti sa dekeirhs sleehw s’trac maets eht dna
,mlap reh tif ot depahs yllaicepse saw tlih ehT
.deilper acceB ”,ti rof drow ruoy ekat lliw I“
licnuoC yrtnuoC rehtoM eht fo ekalgnoL ssetnuoC eht rof stnega era eW
hpmuirt ni gnilrans ,wap ni lotsip xobreppep
erif no esuoheraw elohw eht tes dluoc gniht sihT
,reffaG-dnoM ralohcS .su htiw pu sehctac
,selfir htiw demra sreidlos nezod s’rekab a gnigrogsid dna tlah a ot gnihceercs
”,ton dluohs yeht os ,nwod yaw eht no enoyna kcurts ew eveileb ton od I“
.daed nosrep rehtona hsiw I esuaceb si ti
etulas trams a reh evag eH
.eltsacerof eht otni detrocse saw ralohcs eht sa
,ereh yaw eht lla ti pihs enoemos dah uoy oS“