”feihT a hctaC oT“
”.ti revo teg ot elba eb dluohs eH“
.ereh su tnaw t’ndid uoy taht yrreP dlot tsuj ev’dluoc uoy esuaceb ereh gnieb su tneser t’ndluow uoY
,niaga pu depmuj yrreP
”.elttab gnimoc eht rof sevren ym ydaets oT .ekatrap ot retlehs siht tfel I“
,tser eht no sehsub dna seert
.ni emac ew nehw seno wen pu llor ot su llet saw od ot dah uoy lla ,ytteL dna boR rof edisa sretcarahc eseht peek ot detnaw uoy fi“ ,no tnew naeS ”,oS“
?drow sih ekat ot gniog er’uoY“
:yojne esaelP     .dloGlleyK@ ta rettiwT no mih wollof nac uoy dna
”,yrreP“ ”—uoy dlot I“
xe ym si siht“ ,dias tar eht yrreP ”,syuG“
.derumrum eh ”,ereh detsil slleps emos evah I“
,oyaloS dna dreblaH yalp ot enoemos dedeen ew dias eW“ .dias yrreP ”,oN“
”.yrt tsael ta I fi retteb leef mih ekam ll’tI“
.raugaj eht dna enipucrop eht ot denrut naeS ”.thgiR“
,emit siht eihciR dna naeS ot
.wol gniklat ,eihciR ot ni denael dna teehs retcarahc sih koot eH
”.breh gnimlac a worg elpoep yM“ .dereffo acaM
”?emit siht tnereffid s’tahW“ ”?yhW
”…uoy fo owt eht fo oS“
.slezterp raluger ffo er’uoy ,eseht yrt uoy ,raews I
.sretcarahc doog lufwal retteb hcuM“ .srehto eht ot denialpxe eihciR ”,rotagitsevni etavirp a s’naeS“
”,ni evid tsuj s’teL“
.dias naeS ”,yeH“ .dias eh
”.nwod eltteS“ ”—si sihT“
.dehgual naeS ylno tub
.rood rehtona hguorht nehctik eht ot dnuora semoc ti dna yawllah taht ffo s’moorhtab ehT“
.dias yrreP ”,haey hO“
”?egarag gnikrap eht ta nwod su teem ot tfel yrreP emit eht ni moor eht evael uoy fo yna diD“
.dias eh ”,setunim neetfiF“
”.oN“ ”?gnihtemos llor I oD“
.seveiht eht ot yreveiht sevael eh
,RWAR etaerc depleh eH
”.ni ti yrub ot lluks a dna exa na em eviG
ainrofilaC ni sevil eH
.ruof eht fo desserd yltbus tsom eht saw eh dna
”.esac siht evloS .yakO
,dias raugaj dna xnyl ehT
.xe s’naeS dnuora gnieb tuoba deirrow elttil a neeb ydaerla d’eh dna
.elbat eht dnuora gnittis elpoep ruof eht dna
”.lleps eht taefed ot yrt ot evas a llor ot sah pilliF
”?nwod mih mlac uoy t’nac ,mih detad uoY“ .sreksihw sih tuo gniffulf ,deffins ramolA
”?slezterp eht ekat uoy fo rehtie diD“
”.taht eveileb t’nac llits I“
.etteragic a gnikoms demim enipucrop ehT
,ylruos elttil a ,dias yrreP
”.slezterp ym koot skrej uoy fo eno hcihw wonk ot tnaw I“
srerutnevda fo ytrap evarb a dedeen ohw gnik draziw liarf dna dlo eht fo
liat gnikcilf s’eihciR tap ot elbat eht rednu gnihcaer ,dias naeS
.sregnif sih neewteb ti gnillor saw dna eid dedis-ytnewt a pu dekcip dah dneirfyob siH ”?tahw ,iH“ ”?eihciR
.gnihctiwt liat ,deppots yrreP
yrots eht evaew ramolA ot denetsil naeS elihw ecid gnillor erew yeht dna
.eciov nairabrab sih ni gniklat llits
.pu dekrow lla teg ton s’teL .kooL“
.raugaj eht ta dekool eH
”.kcab emoc llits thgim yehT
.dias ramolA ”,thgir llA“
.seye s’pilliF otni ssorca dekool naeS
”.emag ruoy nioj su gnittel rof sknahT“ .dias naeS ”,iH“
,kcab naeS dellup dna moor gnivil eht ta kool eno koot eihciR   dloG lleyK yb
”.tuoba kniht ot gnik-draziw eht htiw noitaitogen gib a tog ev’uoY
”.gnihtyna nevorp t’nevah uoY
.boR thguorb pilliF tub ,emag eht ot ytteL thguorb I“ .deddon acaM
.aedi na dah neht dna
.decnuonna pilliF ”,lleps eht tsiser ton lliw I“
”.flesruoy yb lla taht fo boj doog a gniod er’uoY“
.feilebsid fo snoitamalcxe edam htob yrreP dna acaM dna ,dias ramolA
.xnyl eht dna ,enipucrop eht ,raugaj eht ssorca tpews regnif siH
,slevon dna seirots sih rof drawA ltoyoC a dna sdrawa rojaM asrU evlewt now sah ohw ,dloG lleyK yb
”.ti enod evah t’ndluoc uoY“
.tuo kaerf yletelpmoc ot gniog t’nsaw yrreP taht mih erussaer dna
.dias—ramolA—xnyl eht
.did eh tahw yltcaxe od ot tnaw t’ndid naeS nehw dah eh yaw eht
”.snaem doog lufwal tahw wonk I“ ”—eb os
,steehs delffuhs sreyalp ehT
”.ramolA MG ruo dna ,pilliF nairabrab ruo
,doog lufwal s’eH“ .detniuqs eH
.dexaler elbat elohw ehT
”.hturt eht no sdneped ytrap ruo fo ytinu eht dna dettimmoc neeb sah emirc A“
,deunitnoc yrreP ”,siht dnA“
.esuoh eht deretne uoy emit eht morf uoy was I
.9102 hguorht snoisses sti fo hcae ta detcurtsni sah dna
.riahc sih ni ylivaeh nwod tas raugaj ehT
,eciov sih desiar yrreP ”!llub si sihT“
.neeuq nogard eht fo rial dnuorgrednu eht ot gnireffo sih ekat ot
.gniyalp peek ot detnaw ew fi su rof ni sretcarahc wen tup dluoc uoy ,hguoht ,kcab emoc od yeht fI“
.doog ylbakramer erew yllaer hcihw
.naeS demlac sdrac eht hguorht gnilffir fo noitom eht tsuJ
.gninnur saw eh eludom a erew yretsym eht hguoht sa
,pilliF fo tnorf ni teehs retcarahc eht no eman eht ees ot revo denael eH
.nairabrab a s’eH“
.tnemucod a hguorht dellorcs dna tuo daPi na dellup xnyl ehT
”?setunim neetfif ,tahw ,saw tahT“
.elbat eht dnuora dekool naeS
htolc etihw a gnuh hcihw revo
”.eihciR dneirfyob sih dna naeS
.meht evah ot ton gnirehtag siht detnaw enoemoS
”—siht ekil steg eh nehW“
”.taht od neve t’ndid I dna loohcs hgih ni D&D deyalp uoY
”?suoires uoy erA“ ”.pilliF nO“
.evaw a htiw mih dessimsid tar ehT
.taorht sih deraelc acaM ”.yllautcA“
.elbat eht rednu wap s’naeS rof dehcaer eihciR dna
”.sknaht ,yrreP ,teehs eht daer nac I“ ”—tog s’ehS
.sreksihw sih debbur naeS
”.detrats siht teg nac ew nehT
”.ereh enoyreve fo sdneirf erew ohw elpoep elpuoc A
.hgual trohs a htiw dexaler eihciR
neercs detniap ylthgirb a dniheb elbat eht fo daeh eht ta xnyl ehT
:flesmih ti dias eH
”?slezterp sih yrreP kcab evig uoy lliw
”.won ereht ton er’yeht tub ,retnuoc eht no meht tup uoy was I .slezterp eht ot deneppah tahw wonk t’nod I“
,slezterp eht ot flesmih depleh eh sllor neewteb ni dna
.sdneirf s’yrreP fo tnorf ni tuoyal a laed ot evah t’ndluow eh depoh eh hguoht ,sdrac fo kced eht rof tekcop sih otni dehcaer eH
.esle enoemos eb ot sretcarahc rieht tnaw t’ndid tsuj I“
,ot detnaw eh naht ylprahs erom elttil a ekops naeS
.kool a degnahcxe acaM dna ramolA
!dlrow ysatnaf nmad a ni sevil eH
”,erutnevda retaerg a no won krabme yeht tub ,sedarmoc tnailav deedni era yehT“
”,yrreP ,pu tuhS“ .nwod tas yrreP
,siht derongi tar ehT
,ti retfa traeh elttil a dedda dna
”.sdneirf ,tem lleW“ ,detnurg enipucrop eht tub ”,yeH“
”?flesruoy yojne dna tuo llihc dna og ti tel uoy lliw ,sezigolopa dna slezterp eht kcab sevig eh fI
.sgniht od ,elpoep ees ,erom tuo teg dluohs ew gniyas eno eht er’uoY“ ”.hu hU
.9002 fo levoN yaG tseB rof drawA wobniaR eht now-oc "noitisoP fo tuO"
”.feiht eht dniF .naeS“
”.yaN“ .dias ramolA ”,oN“
.tsrif ekops ramolA tub ,htuom sih denepo dna ,oot nwod tas yrreP
?gniyalp er’ew elihw eman laer sih yb mih llac su tel neve t’now ohw yug sihT
.uoy eb ot dah fo tros ti ,ramolA t’nsaw ti derugif I ecnO
.ti ezeeuqs dna wap s’flow der rehto eht rof hcaer naeS edam hcihw
”.uoy ot eil t’ndid eh yllacinhcet os gnihtemos ro ’daerb drah‘ slezterp sllac eh ebyaM
si yrots s’yadot dna
”.looc erew ohw sdneirf owt dah I dias I dna
.steehs degnahcxe meht fo owt eht neht dna
”.ti ot desu eb dluohs uoy tuB“
,eihciR dna naeS rof tuo thguorb steehs retcarahc knalb
.smra sih dedlof yrreP
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.od ot gniht thgir eht s’ti esuaceB“
”,moorhtab eht ot tnew I“
”.enod era esoht nehw srebmem ytrap wen owt otni nur ll’uoy ebyam dna
.kcab ylidaets dekool enipucrop ehT
,riahc sih ni kcab denael naeS ”.yakO .taerG“
”?thginot retnuoc eht morf slezterp eht evom uoy diD“
.enipucrop dna xnyl eht ot denrut eH
.daeh sih detlit naeS
.htob naeS dna uoY“
.gnidloh saw naeS teehs eht ta devaw yrreP
”?thgir ,yllacificeps uoy tuB“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.nehctik eht otni kcab pilliF dewollof dna
.laed gib a ton s’ti ,yllaeR“ .dias ramolA ”,syuG“
.yaw oN“ .gnirepsihw dna s’flow der rehto eht ot esolc elzzum sih gnittup
,moc.dloglleyk.www ta elbaliava si skoob sih dna mih tuoba noitamrofni eroM
.dias naeS ”,ecid ekil t’nod I“
.ti no ssorc der detniap-dnah a htiw
?thgiR .ffuts dna semirc evlos uoY“
levon demialcca sih dna
,kcab emoc nac boR dna ytteL os sretcarahc wen pu llor ew fi ,acaM
.temleh llabtoof rehtael yemit-dlo na
.god dna srentrap sih htiw emoh gniyats yltnerruc si dna
”.ekoC a teg ot nehctik eht ot tnew I“
.xnyl eht ot revo denael naeS
,nettirw d’eh hcihw no repap fo eceip a mih dewohs dna naeS dewoble eihciR
.swap desiar sevlow der owt ehT
.yllufthguoht xnyl eht dedrager naeS
.kcor a sa drah ton tub ypsirc er’yeht dna me‘ no secips fo dnelb siht ekil tog yehT“
”…toN .ti s’taht ,ecid dellor dna sretcarahc dah eW“
.seveiht eht ot yreveiht evael I“
.eduD“ .dias eh ”,haeY“
.emag eht lortnoc uoY
)mih dlot dah naeS ”,ssenisub pu tes ot ecalp dab yllaer a saw sageV
”.looc er’yehT“ .dias pilliF
”.yhw tuo tniop ot ecin eb thgim ti thguoht I tuB
,don gnirewsna sih was ,eihciR ta decnalg naeS
”.lleps eht tsac I“
.htaerb a koot naeS
”!detropmi er’yehT
”,kcid uoy ,kcab slezterp eht eviG“
.kcab denael naeS
.naeS drawot devaw yrreP ”!skcid eb oT“
,snoitaitogen ruoy trats nac uoy neht dna ,slezterp eht teg mih tel ew t’nod yhw
”…oS .yenrotta xat a m’I dnA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
trihs liamniahc a detrops raugaj egral a ,enipucrop eht ot txeN
”?slezterp gnissim eht fo esac ehT“
,dloG lleyK yb ”feihT a hctaC oT“
mih fo tnorf ni sdraob eht deiduts ramolA
”?nwo ruoy trats ot tnaw ro sretcarahc rieht tnaw syug uoY“
.pilliF“ saw ti taht tnemesumeb emos htiw was dna
”.nehctik eht otni nettog evah dluoc I
.pu dekool ,nidalap-raugaj eht ,acaM
.ti tsac tsuj uoY“
.feiht nexiv ruo ,rebmA s’tahT“
.tsael ta tif taht ,lleW ”.pilliF“
ti fo trap no krowkcirb nward yledurc htiw sllaw eht gnirevoc repap rehctub egral eht
”,flesmih rof lla meht stnaw ohw enoemoS“
.seye sih revo nwod gnillaf tpek taht tah ytniop htolc dna kaolc elprup a ni tar a saw ni meht del eh sa gninrut dnA
.yldlim dias naeS ”,thgir llA“
.naeS ta detniop dna pu til tar ehT
”.uoy gniees ydobon htiw nehctik eht ni erew uoy fo owt oS“
.dias eh ”,yrros m’I“
.thgieh s’acaM fo trohs sehcni wef a pu gnimoc os neve dna seotpit sih no gnidnats
,moor gnivil eht drawot derutseg eH
.teehs retcarahc sih deiduts eihciR elihw deksa naeS ”?slezterp temruoG“
”?elpoep evigrof ot eno eht eb ot evah syawla I od yhW“ .kcab riahc sih dekcik tar ehT ”!oN“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.gniyl er’yeht fi wonk ll’uoy ,taht tsac dna seye s’enoemos otni kool uoy fI .ezaG gnitarteneP evah uoY .ereht ,haeY“
pu tog ramolA ”.nwod eltteS“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.htob meht dekil lla eW
”.trats a rof taht s’ereht os“ ,dias eihciR ”,xof a ton m’I dna elamef ton m’I“
”.tniop eht fo tros s’tahT“
ekil dekool tahw dna sdraug redluohs htiw etalptsaerb rehtael dedduts a erow enipucrop a ,thgir sih oT
.teehs eht dennacs eihciR ”.ees em teL“
”.kcab emoc yeht epoh I“ .elbat eht no swoble sih detser ramolA
,acaM ta kool ot denrut elbat elohw ehT ”.ton did I ,oN“
”?gnilaets rof nidalap eht hsinup ebyam dnA“
”?ecnahc sih s’tahW“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.felA dog-nus eht fo rewollof a ,cirelc a s’eH
”!uoY“ .ekas s’eihciR rof
.retcarahc s’boR eb nac uoy ,eihciR .ereH“ .nwod tas yeht sa eihciR dna naeS ta repap gnihsup
.deralg raugaj ehT ”.eduD“ .dias yrreP
”?slezterp eht evah ot su tnaw t’ndid enoemoS .sU“
tcelaid nwo sih ni nairabrab eht noitseuq ot woh tuoba kniht ot detrats eH
”?slleps gnillet-hturt ,ekil ,meht fo yna erA“
siht no gnihton si erehT“ ”.retnuoc eht nO“
”.eerht esoht fo eno s’tI
.sdneirf sih rof tuo gnikool tsuj saw acaM“ .dias naeS
.yawa reh gnipeek s’ohw eno eht s’boR ,IYF dna dneirf ym s’ytteL“ .dias acaM
,woN .ekatsim sih timda ot nidalap eht fo elbon yrev s’tI“
.ysuolaej dna sgnileef truh ton
.ramolA neeb evah dluoc llits tI“
”,yalp-elor ot si tniop ehT“
,pohskrow gnitirw yrruf laitnediser tsrif eht
”.puorg eht ni lrig a tel evah t’ndluohs ew uoy dloT“
.slezterp yub nac eW
,ynnuf eb ot gniyrt ,dias eihciR ”,feiht a m’I“
”.erutan doog ruoy rof uoy drawer thgim tsuj gnik draziw eht ,og ti tel dna tuo llihc uoy fi esuaceb dnA“ .neercs sih revo dekeep ramolA
”.krej a ekil kool em ekam ot gniyrt er’uoy os taht ekil t’nod syug uoy dna sdneirf gnirb ot teg I“
”.hu ,no ezaG gnitarteneP tsac ot tnaw I“
”.sretcarahc rieht ekat ll’eW“ .dias eihciR
,stidnab dna sretsnom tuoba yrrow ot dah ylno yeht erehw dlrow ysatnaf eht otni evid ot won regae meht fo lla
.ramolA ot denrut naeS ”.yakO“
.pilliF yb dewollof ,deraeppaer ramolA
.deddon raugaj ehT ”?acaM“
,yawyna meht dellor eh tub ,naeS ot drawkwa dna yvaeh tlef ecid ehT
.deppans yrreP ”,ereh ton m’I ekil em tuoba gniklat potS“
”?ereh tog ew nehw dias uoy ekil ,sretcarahc wen gnivah su tuoba deklat lla uoy daH
.ecid eht fo eno pu dekcip naeS ”.yltcefreP“
”.ti s’taht kniht t’nod I“
”,decalpsim tog tsuj yeht erus m’I“
!skcub neetfif ekil tsoc slezterp esohT“
.hguorht siht klat s’teL“ .dias eh ”,thgir llA“
.slezterp eht yub dluoc uoy fo ynA .thgir s’acaM“
?siht no emit ruo etsaw ot tnaw yllaer uoY .sruoh elpuoc a ni og attog I
.meht evah ot tsuj eb t’nac evitom eht oS
”?meht koot uoy fo eno hcihW“ .taes sih fo tuo depmuj yrreP ”?tahW“ ”’.retnuoc‘
?thguorb yrreP slezterp temruog eht teg ot tnaw uoy ,pilliF .thgir llA“ .dennirg ramolA
”.emoc ot detnaw ehS
”.dennalp ffuts looc hcum os tog ev’I .ydaerla gnik draziw gnikaerf eht ot teg ot syug uoy tnaw I“ .denworf ramolA
,)llaw eht ni seloh ni nward serutaerc llams htiw(
”,siht ta doog ytterp er’uoY“
,riaf ecnassianeR a rof edam neeb ylraelc dah taht cinut a revo kaolc eulb thgirb a erow
neht“( yllacitarre gnivaheb elpoep dnuora tca ot woh wonk t’ndid eh tub yug ydaets a saw eihciR
”.hguorht siht klat em pleh tsuJ“
,deveirter erew slezterp eht ,hguone nooS
”?meht laets enoemos dluow yhW
.enoemos gnicalper er’eW“
,ecid dna repap fo steehs ni derevoc elbat nedoow egral eht
.snoisivorp on ees I“
”.retnuoc eht morf slezterp eht devom ohw su llet t’ndluow llits taht tub ,esuoh eht hcraes dluoc ew sseug I“
.eihciR ta derats enipucrop ehT
”.sruoh rof emag siht no dekrow I“
,acaM nidalap ruo si“
”.ti htrow os er’yeht tub gab lamron a semit eerht ekil tsoc yehT
.pilliF drawot tuo wap a tsurht neht dna tnemom a rof desuap ohw
.noitseuq nwo sih derewsna neht dna ,deksa eihciR
”?ssenisub ruoy nur uoy woh siht sI“ .pu tog acaM ”.enasni si sihT“
.sdrac eht gnilffir sregnif sih
,hguorht tfel d’eh yawrood eht ni deraeppaer enipucrop ehT
”.thgin eht niur ot yrt ot evah t’ndid uoY
”?emos thguorb uoy niatrec uoy erA
”feihT a hctaC oT“
.elbat eht ot txen gnicap ,demuf yrreP
.trihs s’nidalap sih debbur raugaj ehT ”.oN“ ”?uoy diD“
”,gnitad detrats ytteL dna boR ecnis reve sreyalp trohs er’eW“