”.krow nac uoy fi ,uoy ekat ll’I
.em ezingocer t’nod uoy ezilaer I
.taht tuoba lla wenk eH .erus ,hO ?neila nA
.esrow saw siht tub
d’eh edaj taht ni dna
,tekcaj ym barg dluoc I erofeB
,ytrap eht otni tuo kcab tnew ew erofeb no kcab stnap ym tup ylbaborp dluohs I dias uoY
!ebirt lavir rieht taefed ylerus dluow yeht
.sgel ym morf gnihtolc htrae dlo ym fo srettat eht deppirts ehs sa derats dna
,drah saw krow ehT
,seye nailitper reh ni sraet htiw ,dna
,tlahpsa ot yaw evag neht hcihw ,rebmun dnoyeb
rats kcor hsiugor a er’uoy esuaceb
.thgilnus eht otni deklaw I
61 taeH ni dehsilbup yllanigiro saw yrots ehT
.terref neila ehT .em dednimer uoy ,neilA
”?lrig tcefrep eht teem ll’uoy nehw wonk ot ,raed ,retteb leef ti t’ndluoW“
.reh ot delaever eb dluow etaf ym ecafrus sti nopu taht demialc dna
,reteiuq tib a ecalpemos dereffo uoy nehw os
.trohs kool yks eht edam yeht hgih os erew sniatnuom eht erehw
nwotnwod ytrap a fo uoy dnimer I
”,dnah ruoy fo og tel I yrros m’I“
,lrig a egnahc nac srats eht ,lleW
krad dna tnelis dih ew
,dah I sa tsuj ,oot ereh dehsarc dah ehS
ecaf reh no rorret eht ees dluoc I
,nopaew sih fo esu reporp eht tuoba nrael ot hcum dah eh tuo snrut tI
.od t’ndluohs I dias uoy gniht eno eht—
,evoba raf yks eht ni sehsalf eht nees dah yehT
.tnemssarrabme elbatrofmocnu htiw nageb neila na htiw emit tsrif yM .deb reh otni
.neht ,tnew I erehw wonk t’nod I
.ecnatsid a ta ylno fi ,uoy wenk I
,tsacnwod daeh htiW
,ebirt lacol a ot dlos saw I dna
.nwod dekcils srae ym dna
,dab neeb dah ytrap ehT
oD fo ecioV eht ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
kciht os saw noitarbelec eht erehw
tenalp retaw-kcab eht otni dehsarc dna
.seimene rieht dna
,edaf sthgil noen eht htaeneb tlep ruoy fo wolg nedlog eht was I
no traeh ym tes dah I tahw taht gnizilaer tsuj si
srood denepo yot s’niatpac eht gnieb dna
,dlrow eht naht eroM
.dlog fo tuo edam si ruf sih dna
,anaugi na ekil daeh a dna selacs elprup htiw nairiatlA na
.tiw dna lliw ym deneprahs dah setarip eht htiw raey A
.sebor rieht htaeneb morf gniliart
.rehcaet eht emaceb tneduts eht
.dias eh ,emadaM eht ksa oG
bro eht revo sdnah gnikahs dleh ehS
,skoob ym htiw eb dna emoh og ot detnaw I .divaD ,uoy knahT
.dellips yltneloiv
,surutcrA ot tuo ti welf dna
,llew detaert saw I tub
.seitrap rehto fo stol erew ereht dna
,deeps laicalg ta yb gniggard sruoh dna derob werc eht htiw ,syad esoht nO
.plug naht rehtar
.dias uoy ,ydal lufituaeb a tsiser t'ndluoc uoY .em ,llew ,sa
pmal teerts nekorb a htiw
,allerbmu ym rof kcab og dluohs I dias I
tfos gnar senot riehT .dioretsa dna
,ronoh ruo ni tsaef a dleh nalc eht ,tfel ew erofeB
.emit txen uoy rof yrots wen a evah ll'I
,delaever si cigam eht nehw
.nameltneg a hcus erew uoY
.”dog“ rieht sa desop taht knim derruf-etihw eht gninroda
.flesym deyojne I
secips ygnat dna teews rieht woh ro
.der delb lla ew ,htaenrednu tub
.eno eb dluoc uoy ,daetsnI
.wohs ti tel t’ndid I tub
.srats neewteb secaps eht denekrad
.tropria eht ta thguob dah I etalocohc eht rof egnahcxe ni
.don a dna elims A
.deirt I .dias uoy
dlog fo ruf htiw
,ti evah ot em detnaw eH .tnuh eht fo
slautir terces rieht htiw
.sserp flowafoS yb
,reh ot ycehporp ym detaeper I
.seirots s’rehto hcae raeh ot
”,divaD ,dnah ym ekaT“
.evaw citlatsirep a ni yawa uoy deirrac ti dna
.revo si tseuq yM
dias uoy ,ksam ruoy ta kooL
doohretsis a tub
,trap tnatropmi eht saw gnideelb eht tub ,neerg delb yehT
.latrop eht ta em doots yeht neht dnA
,nus muirab a rednu dekrow ew yad yB
,uoy ta dehgual tsomla I
.reed nehtraE na nees reven d’ehs esuaceb em dekcip
,hsarc eht morf revocer ot emit on neviG .eniN-ryL fo
,niaga dekniw uoY
,erofeb em wonk ot teg ot emit eht nekat t'ndah uoy taht
,dworc gninevar eht ni
.yxalag eht fo erutan eht dna
tas modsiw fo stneicna eht sniatnuom fo spot eht ta erehw ,tsaE raF ehT
”.desitrevda sa etarucca ro etelpmoc sa ylraen ton si mra noirO eht fo seiceps citoxe ot ediug etarucca dna etelpmoc ym taht ees I“
,sknird naht skoob ot desu erom lrig yhs A
.gninrom eht ni flesym etah d’I esuaceb
,ylleb reh ssorca rellams werg yeht tub
,sey a rof taht koot I
er“ ot reh htiw deripsnoc I
,taht erafraw fo snossel derebmemer I
.ti ni uoy dah ytrap taht ecnis yllaicepsE
.ecaps retuo ot em ekat ll’uoy dna
,srats eht hguorht maws ew ,yad yB
.sedis lla no em dednuorrus taht erutaerc elgnis a ekil gnivom
.dnuos tuohtiw evom ot woh em dewohs eh sa
,nodnoL ,notxirB ni talf elttil A .rood ruoy ta
.t’ndid yeht tpecxe ,lleW
,gnihsup dna gnivohs seidoB
.erehpsomta reppu eht ni yltneloiv detargetnisid
”.mih dnif ot pu uoy yrrac lliw yeht dna ,srats eht morf sdneirf ym llac lliw I
,skoob ecnatsid-gnol ym morF
.evael ym koot dna
,edaj fo eceip etirovaf sih tpek dah eh
,’sekips-elttab‘ elbon ym dna
.ytpme erew steerts ehT
,dessap emit sa tub
.saw terref a tahw em deksa yehT
.xamilc sti dehcaer raw nairyL-nageV nettogrof eht ,evoba raF
,ssarg gnol eht hguorht yerp ym llik dna klats ot deen t’ndid I
.delliflufnu em tfel snossel sih tub
terces s’retto eht
.em nevig dah noiL taht edaj eht mih evag I
ssalg a em dednah uoY
.ssem ruoy pu naelc em depleh dna
xof a fo eugor gnihsad a
.esorp yrewolf tub gnihton neeb dah ,neht litnu pu
,seert ylimaf evitcelloc eht enurp ot thguof dah sroirraw ecreif rieht ecno erehw dna
.rats kcor neila hsiugor a gnieb tuoba tsaob tsuj ot evah t’nod uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.emit eht ta gnihgual erew uoy hguoht
semoh rieht fo sgnos gnis meht ot denetsil I thgin yb dna
,desufnoc saw I ”.hO“ ”.tnetnoc dna
.noitpircsed ruoy tif ohw
.esuegleteB ot og ll’I kniht I
swolb wef a evivrus dluoc ohw esohT
.ecaf ym no nwohs evah tsum ti taht
,dias rethgierf eht
,em ot sevlesmeht dellacer dnuorg hgih dna segrahc gniknalf fo stpecnoC
,meht dael ot em htiW
.reed a rof eman dooG .em stius ti dna
,desimorp uoy ,seitrap erom on ,yakO
tabmoc yldog fo smrof eht ni
.revo saw elttab eht
,ssaltuc ym werd xelfeR
.edart ot semoc rotces elohw eht erehw
,cisum eht revo tuohs ot gnivah erew ew ,emit taht yB
.evom ylerab dluoc ew taht
”.tidnab a neeb evah tsum eH
?inadirE atE fo senal ecaps eht ksir ot tnaW
.yaw eht em dewohs lerrab gninrub a raen gnidnats urug esiw a dna ,deirc I
,htron eht ni tes nus dnoces eht elihw
!pihs ecaps ruoy ees dluohs I .dekniw uoY
,emit a rof meht htiw deyats I oS
,tenalp dlo derit ym ta dnuora gnikool ,won tub
,evoba raf dewolg taht rats wen taht meht dlot I
?ylevian ton fi ,nigeb erutnevda na dluohs esle woh tub ,esruoc fo ,gnorw saw I
,eno emaceb sebirt owt
”!esrevinu eht uoy wohs ll’I dna
.sgel reh neewteb elbisivni hgin erew yeht taht
.hcamots ym ni swoble dna kcab ym ni sredluohs
ebirt gnisoppo ruO
.riaper enigne cirehpsomta fo syaw eht ni esiw osla saw ehs
gnineve eht fo dne eht yb dna ,srebmem citoxe rieht dna shtuom dna sregnif dna sdrow htiw tnuom-elttab eht pota em depihsrow yehT
,erew uoy ereht neht tuB
,spihw eht htaeneb tneps I syad gnoL
.ecneirepxe wen a yletinifed saw tI
,eno ton yb detneserper
,raw ecaps eht fo dne eht fo evoba hgih skrowerif eht nI
.uoy dnif ot erehw wonk dluow sniatnuom rieht fo spot eht ta nem esiw eht spahrep
uoy ta daeh ym detniop I
,ssorC sgniK ot ebut eht edor ew dna
?surutcrA dnuora saluben eht ni ecnad ot tnaw uoy t’noD
,hcum oot tog ti nehw sreltna ym fo dne ssenisub eht tem flow roop A
.feiht a uoy ekam t’nseod ti hguoht neve
,citsaisuhtne erew sexof nairyL ehT
,kcar enif a hcus gnivah em ekil lrig on tuoba ekoj a edam neve uoY
seiceps a yb detanicsaf erew yeht
.em ot dehctertstuo dleh llits dnah ruoy
.ecaf ruoy no kcohs htiw em ta kool uoY
.noitseuq taht derewsna evah tsum reh evag I noisufnoc fo kool ehT .deksa ehs
”.mih dnif uoy pleh nac I spahrep dna ,dias eh tahw em llet tuB“
.eurt neeb dah seirots ehT
.ecaps fo diov krad eht deklats selissim dna dehsalf sresaL
.smra nepo htiw em democlew yeht
!tsaot a evig dna spuc eht esiaR
,yadot ,ereh dnats ot emac I woh s’tahT
,enod d’I gnippis fo daetsni gniplug eht lla morf tib a gnimmiws saw daeh ym fi nevE
em dekcohs os ymotana ym fo detcepxe d’ehs tahw fo tpecnoc ehT
,lla was ,lla wenk ohw
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht fi ro
.pihsgalf deyortsed eht fo wolg gnidecer ylkciuq eht sdrawot pu ecnalg a dna gnidnatsrednu fo kniw a htiw
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.psalc ruo trapa gniggard
.sretsam-revals erutluv citsidas eht htiw emit ym ot derapmoc tsael ta
,noziroh eht no uoy was I
.teelf eht niojer dna
.yrrap eht dna tsurht eht—
.terref a er’uoy taht tcaf eht revoc ot tseb yrev sti gniod
.kcab dekool reven dna elbat sknird eht ta em detisoped neht
.ereht neeb t’ndah enob dna elcsum dna ruf fi sa tuc hcihw
,em htiw hguorht saw ti nehW
.edis yreve morf ni gnimool dworc a saw ereh dna
.modeerf ym nevig saw I raey a retfa taht ecivres ym htiw ehs saw detale oS
,niatnuom eht fo urug eht evoba derevoh tI
.meht rof thgif ot em dednetni yeht woh em wohs ot deen dluow yeht—eil tnatalb a—
.srats erew em dniheB
!delaeveR ynitseD dnA thguoS setaF“
.daeh sih deddon urug ehT ”.esruoc fO“ ”.neila na neeb evah tsum eH .sessalgnus dna tekcaj gnizama na dah eH“ ”.ylekil tsom ,stsaob eldI ?uoy rof gnis eh diD“ ”.rats kcor a neeb evah tsum eH
raeps a eldnah ot woh em dewohs eH
.dnim ym fo tuo elttil a tnew I kniht I ,tsriF
dop efil eht ot delf I
.em dednimer uoy ,neila eht divaD
raeps tnereffid a eldnah ot woh em dewohs eh nehT
sdnah ym ni thgil-rehtaef saw kcip ehT
,tauqs dna dewob emaceb
noitcerid s’tenalp ruo ni nworht saw taht lenparhs drawyaw dna
sreltna ym no spord eht htiw doog dekool I dias uoy tub
,ruf gniwolg ym ta kool neht ,hsulb uoY .ksa I
,uoy dnif ot tseuq ym fo draeh niatpac etarip ym nehW
.htraE no kcab esrow raf derudne d’I
dettimda dna delims uoY
gnitseretni tsom thguoht yeht sevals esoht elots dna
,hguot saw ti fi deksa I
,setarip eht morf denrael dah I lla htiW
tabmoc fo yaw eht ni reniart lanosrep ym sa ecalp sih ekat ot deronoH
.niaga uoy ees ot detnaw I
,ereht tuo ecalp yracs a s’tI
!em tuoba taht dias reve dah eno oN
.ecnarudne rieht fo dne eht ta erew ohw esoht rof meht koot
eniw ecaps laiceps rieht rof epicer eht—
nehctik s’tsoh eht morf lewot a elots uoY
.yhw erus neve ton m’I dna
.gnol yrev rof ton tub
.ohw wonk ydaerla I“ .dias I ”,on hO“
,su evoba raf noitcurtsed lufetsaw fo tnemom taht nI
”,sepyt lla sekat ti ,lleW“ ”.eh a s’eh dnA
,yteixna ym ni em detrofmoc yehT
.sreltna ym dellac yeht tahw si hcihw
annavas eht fo sklaw gnol eht evivrus ot woh em hcaet ot dereffo eh tub ,eman ruoy
.dlo eht no erutluv kcen-dellirf eno fo pihw eht eraps dluow noitcartsid A
.praw morf dellup yltneloiv saw pihs ym
,etalosed neeb evah dluow
,dnammoc s’knim eht htiw pu kcab tem eW
”.gnidaeR dnuoP neT
retaw eht revo ffo gnizag
,dnah sih dloh ot tnaem I
desrev-llew saw I elihw ,taht deugra I
.sevals rehto htiw smraf negordyh rieht dekrow I
,dog a nihtiw tiurf raeb ot ylekilnu saw dees s’latrom a taht meht dlot I
.eno ylraelc saw I hcihw fo—
,no em dellup uoY
.did uoy tuo denrut tI
.enalp eht no tpels I
,eilseL .edisni dils dna
doolb morf nrob si
.enod reven d’I gnihtemos s’taht dettimda I
ebirt eht fo tser eht fo gniraeh fo tuo tas
.did yeht yrt dnA
.nekops eb ot dedeen sdrow oN
,spih ym thguac swap fo riap A
.etsah htiw emadaM dias
.ot detnaw uoy fi sreltna ym hcuot dluoc uoy taht uoy dlot dna
emoh fo gnas sevals wollef ym ,elihw eht llA
,dias uoy ,eman doog a si eilseL
rehtegot sdees wen dehsiruon yeht won
.rats kcor a eb tsum uoy
.erutangis praw thguondaerd teelf sinaC a ezingocer ot dna
.dog nwo rieht htrof thguorb
pu evig ot tuoba saw I
sebirt owt fo shtgnerts eht taht
,deksa dna sdnah ym koot ehS
,gnol si ydob siH ?deksa I
,ebut eht ot kcab spets ym decart I
em dessik eniw ecaps fo gnillems elzzum yreksihw A
er sdrow rehto ni ro
.yawyna uoy knaht dias I
.redluohs ym no saw dnah ruoy dna ,thgindim ot nwod gnikcit saw neB giB
.derutan-doog saw gnibbir ehT
.niar eht otni tuo nar ew dna
.derewoc I dna ,degnorht dworC
.lla dootsrednu I .lla was I
,egami dna fles htiw selggurts nwo ym fo meht dlot I nehW
sliat ekil-tac kcalb htiw
.kcurt a naht regral ylerab
.emoh emoc ot steg enoyreve ton dna
deriapmi saw tnemgduj ym
elttab eht fo gnineve eht nO
.ezigolopa dluoc I erofeb enog saw eh tub
.erusaelp reh htiw dekaos saw elzzum ym dna
dnah ruoy fo og tel dah I
decnad dna delruc ymotana citoxe rieht sa
.sgniliaf rieht dna serutaef rieht
,draeh reven dah yeht terces a fo ecirp eht rof dna
”.taht htiw yako er’uoy fI .yats ot ekil d’I kniht I“
.htrae gniklaw eht retfa dlrow eht fo em dlot eh dna
.tuoba daer neve reven ev’I sgnihT
”.eromyna ma I ohw ton s’tI“
.noitareneg txen retaerg a raeb thgim
.ytisoiruc yb derehtoms saw tub
,em si eilseL taht ezilaer ot uoy rof sdnoces erom wef a sekat tI .yas uoy ”,sey hO“
.rac a rof hguone egral neve t’nsi taht
tnecsediri erew srehtaef esohw
.niaga pirg ym hctac dluoc I litnu
ta elbaliava yhpargoilbib eritne sih dnif nac uoy
,deb reh no em dial niatpac ehT
dah taht lessev nailivic a rof emit on dah allitolf ehT
!thgie ,enin ,net saw ti nehT
eugnot ym no decnad
.sredael labirt eht ot dellac I
oga gnol os neeb dah ti sa tsuj—
,erehpsomta reppu eht ni sevlesmeht tneps srats gnitoohs sA
thguob eb ylno nac taht ycnerruc a si ecneirepxe dna evian saw I tub
elims eht fo tsohg a em evig uoY ”.yako s’tahT“
,srats eht fo seman ehT
,raeps lanosrep sih em evag
.snoitpecnocerp ylhtrae ym dehs dah I
stsirw ruoy dnuora stelecarb gniwolg dah uoY
yaw evag neht hcihw
,meht emalb yldrah dluoc I ,llitS
.dnas fo yleritne edam noil a dnuof I
siloportem eht fo seitisortsnom leets gnirewot eht nehT
spihs reknuj rieht leuf ot negordyh eht koot yehT
,on—gnippis neeb d’I nehw
.em otni pu dils htgnel yreppils a dna
.tsael ta ,raf taht mih htiw hctih dluoc I tub
,lla dna repparw ,etalocohc eht deruoved eh ,thgin tahT
.leurc erew skaeb dna
.tneduts tpa na hcus neeb d’I ecnis
,divaD er'uoy swonk enoyna s'ohw enoyrevE
I dna ”dog“ rehto eht ,noitarbelec ruo morf derevocer ecnO
,lortnoc fo tuo denoissif llits eroc enigne s’thguandaerd eht erehw
.llew em thguat doohretsis eht tub ,sgnits tI
kcab ym otno em dellor uoy sa
.smraf ruo diar setarip did
.erehpsomta rieht evoba ecalp gnikat raw ecaps eht fo snoisolpxe eht dna sresal eht
.seye ruoy treva uoY .reffo I
,tekcop ruoy ni peek uoy enots eht em edart lliw uoy fI
.sdnuow ym devlas sevals rehto eht fo sdnah dnik eht ylno dna
eulb fo slarips gniwolg htiw
,pih ym ta drabbacs sti ni ssaltuc s’etarip eht
.engapmahc eht—gniplug
.em ot detfig dah gnignirbpu htraE ym taht
,srevol xof ruo tuoba delbbiuq eW
.ot rewsna llits I taht enon dias I dna
,suoiretsym dna dedooh erew sretsis ehT
,uoy htiw tfel I fi dnA
,em pleh ton dluoc htrae eht fo stirips eht fI
,redluohs ot redluohS
rae ym otni derepsihw uoy
sreltna eht yb em llup dluow niatpac eht
.gnilhctah a taeb eh nehw
,won stirips eht htiw si eh ees nac I“
sthgin rebmos dna syad toh eht ot detamilcca dah I retfa ylnO
,reenigne rieht gninruter rof sknaht ni dna
”,retsnom a ton m’I tub ,seY“
,esarhp eht etah ot nworg dah I
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,lerdnaK yb
.eldnah devrac dna srehtaef sti htiw
.evol sa suoicerp sa si ria erehw tleb dioretsa na ni
trop eht morf ffiks erusaelp a dekcajih I
?od ot tahw em gnillet eb uoy t’ndluohS“
,rethgierf ralletsretni na tsurt ot naht retteb nwonk evah dluohs I
.redips gnitnuh a ekil ecnuop ot detiaw ew llew ytivarg s’tenalp eht fo edis raf eht nI .trocse on dna
sthguondaerd yratilim fo skluh taerg ,em dnuorA
,trahc rats cihpargoloh a daer ot denrael I
ytrap s’enelrahS ta reed elttil dimit eht eilseL
.rehto hcae fo tuo dna otni dils dna
,tneps dna dekan ereht yal I sA
tenalp eht epacse ot tsurht hguone htiw dop efil dehsarc ym gij-
krej a htiw ekow I
.tenalp emoh rieht fo noziroh devruc revo esor
.scitcat dna ygetarts ssucsid ot licnuoc-raw yvirp a dellac dah I
?tibro ni ereht pu nerhterb decnavda yllacigolonhcet rieht ekil tsuj eb ot
.eloh kcalb eht otni llef dna ,pets a koot I
,toof fo tnorf ni tooF
.snemo ym derorrim ehS
.noitseuq eno rewsna dluow
denrael dna dehctaw I llits tub
.smra ym ni derevihs uoy sa evila dna mraw os erew uoY
.noitatidem ni detativel ohw
skcip fo skcarc eht neewteb llirhs dna
.evael ot emit s’ti
,tnaig sag taerg a fo sgnir eht ni gnitrovac meht dnuof I
.noitanicsaf ti llaC .enog d’uoy erehw gnirednow dna
.noisserpxe gnitrofmoc a dna
.sevitan fo nalc a yb thguac saw I
,elbatrofmoc saw I erus edam uoY
,uoy dessik I ,evif ,xis ,neveS
,edaj eht detekcop ,noil deknaht I
.uoy emalb t’nod I sseug I
”.ruf ylno saw tI“ .dias urug eht
,thgil tlef daeh ym
,eert eht htaeneb dial I dna noiL .taem fo
dias uoy ,sregnif eseht ta kooL .feiht a er’uoy
si yrots s’yadot dna
.dootsrednu I egaugnal ylno eht saw siht taht dettimda I
,dednecsed neila nA
sresiurc detaefed fo skluh tuo denruB
,ydob fo gnol erew yehT
,sretto erew yeht ,daetsnI
.dluow yeht spahrep ,wenk enoyna fI
.noissesbo ti llaC
.esor yteixna dna noitartsurF
.shtolcniol dna rehtael ni dalc
t’ndiD“ .kcab ym ssorca depparts s’taht raeps labirt eht dna
.htuom ym denepo dah I erofeb
.esrevinu eht htiw
,ytleurc rieht fo stcart eht erob kcab yM
,yks eht otni raf tahT
,eman rehtona dah I ebyam fi deksa uoY .decarb I
,dnah ruoy koot I fi dnA
.seY !hO“ .reh ma I dna
.llew em deraperp dah doohretsis eht fo gniniart eht tub ,llits dleh emiT
.tnatropmi t’nsaw ti dias yeht tub
.enots eht devarb I
.dah seiceps rieht eno ylno eht—
.oga srats dna snoom esoht lla nees d’I
.sungyC revo sdioretsa eht morf sretsyo tae ot yaw tcerroc eht denrael I
tuons ym no dnah a htiw dna
.eniw ekam ot sduolc ralletsretni tsav morf lohocla denohpis yeht yaw eht gninrael
”?kaeps uoy od segaugnal citcalagretni ynam woH .dab ooT“
.esnes retteb sekam tahT“
meht dael ot tnaw I diD
.enim sa ylralimis reh detaert dah ebirt reh
,tnuom labirt eht fo xepa eht ta em htiw doots saW’a’luT’C
.rehtegot srebmahc hsulp ni delruc ew thgin yb dna
,tlef ti woh wenk uoy dias dna
,pihs ecaps mils a emac yks eht morf nwoD
,yrots ym draeh yeht nehW
.dnah ym ekat uoy tub ,yawa dekool I
.spil ruoy kcil uoY ”.sey ,lleW“
.rehtona ekil hcum yrev saw tsurht eno taht dnuof I
,terref nedlog A
.deb reh ot kcab em gard dluow niatpac eht
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na gnidaer m'I yadoT
,sepor eht nwohs saw I srelwart knuj dna sreluah deifidom fo teelf rieht draobA
gninrom gniwollof eht yB
.maet a sa ti did ew dna
,tibro otni kcab ti edam ew emit eht yB
.tneiciffe si ttubelttucs etariP
yllacirohpatem htob—
.gniyrt morf meht pots t’ndid taht tub
.won divaD htiw saw I tub
.ti dekil enoyreve yhw ees nac I
.hturt eht llet I ”.od I“ .ekoj uoy
,tenalp ybraen a sdrawot lortnoc fo tuo gnilarips dna deniur senignE
rednow ni dehctaw I dna ,daeh ym ot txen delpuoc slamina gnimriuqs eht fo erom owT
,ecnarongi ym ni tnedifnoC .dnas ot
.dnas dna ksum dna esion fo lluf saw ria ehT
”?neeb sgniht evah woH“ .elbmuts uoy ”,oS“
.thguof dna derekcib sredle ebirt ehT
,lapeN ot delevart I
,dnim s’nam a egnahc ot woh
,em revo hctaw d’ehs deralced ohw
,su rof metsys eht tpews sresiurc yratilim nehw syad gnol eht no dnA
,tsaeb a saw dworc ehT
.emeht eht saw burcs dna nus dna dnas ,edistuO
semoh paehc ot yaw evag sesuoheraW
.liatkcoc naem a sevres taht ereht rab a s’ereht draeh ev’I
.nelots s’eh sllab flog fo noitcelloc evisserpmi na dna
slriws eulb gniwolg tnenamrep ni ruf ym deyd sretto eht
.ecaps ot kcab teg ot tiaw t’nac I
.dne daed a tih dah I wenk I tey ,esolc oS
,llab latsyrc reh ta dehcuorc dnuohdoolB emadaM
.senal ecaps eht derettil spihselttab dna
.wonk stirips eht ylno taht
,pleh sih rof lufetarG
.stirips eht wenk uoY
,og tel t’nod dna
.dias uoy ,erehwyreve neeb d’uoY
thgie netyuL fo sgnir eht hguorhT
,seirots s’lerdnaK fo erom daer ot ekil d’uoy fI
.elohw em dewollaws ti dna
.duol tuo ti yas ot gnivah ton dnuora gnicnad erew uoy yaw eht htiw
.gnipoord droc cirtcele neddih yldab
.yawa yhs uoy dna ,esoporp I
scitsym fo doohretsis a fo em dlot yeht
.emit dna ecaps fo cirbaf eht ni tolb krad A
!seman eurt rieht denrael dna
.slatrom elbmuh eseht gnoma emit ym dneps ot dengied I elihw erac ym ot nevig saw saW’a’luT’C deman
,keew a dna htnom a roF
saW’a’luT’C dna
.doolb dna taews htiw
,evE s’raeY weN saw tI
,enibucnoc ym dna
.moordeb tseug reh ni enod d’ew tahw wonk ot enelrahS tnaw t’ndid uoy esuaceb
!esrevinu eht htiw denummoc dna
”?trahc rats yb etagivan uoy naC“
”.niatpac a dna etarip a er’uoY
”,doohdog ruo ot dnecsa-
kcils dna htooms gnihtemos elihw
.stemoc eht neewteb ni deyalp sdamon derruf-dlog eht erehw rats der eht
,yllacinori spahreP
,hcihw ,cigam neddibrof dnoces eht denrael ev’I
.dnim t’ndid I tub ,deliaf tI
:yojne esaelP   .moc.enilnoyxof.www
.maerd eht decreip thgil sa
.kcis tlef I yllacisyhp os ti derised I
.luos evitisnes a dna teop a
,ecnavda eht demmurd dlaks ruo sA
,llef I ,ecnO
.htiw nigeb ot laer neeb yllaer reven dah
”?tnaw uoy fi ,ereht edir rehtona dnif nac uoy dna
.rehtegot emit ruo rebmemer ot tsaef a em werht yeht
engoloc tnegnirtsa dna ekoms doow fo stnih
,sregnif htiw flesreh daerps ehS
.engapmahc eht ta deplug dna
,og tel t’nod dna dnah ym ekaT
dah ti ekil tsuj
.rats kcor on er’uoy ,ylraelC
.sgnilhtrae roop su gnoma klaw ot srats eht morf nwod gnimoc
.slatsyrc enexoryp no
,eert eht fo stoor eht htaeneB
.noom s’tenalp eht dniheb
.gnignellahc dna edun
,deb reh no kcab dial niatpac ehT
,gniplug eht morf yspit llitS
.yas I ”,t’nevah uoY“
,dlog saw ruf rieht dna
,sreltna ym revo tif t’ndluow dooh ehT
ycnegreme gnimocno yna fo sthgildaeh eht ni ezeerf ot ylekil dna sdnah reh ni skoob htiw htraE no kcab ,em regnuoy A
,seuqinhcet tnatropmi ssel erew etsopir dna yrrap eht hguoht dna
.meht dnif ot erehw dna ,sneila eht tuoba lla swonk ehS
,eert baboab llat a htaeneB
,deralf yteixnA .dias ehs
,erom detcepxe dah I
.delggirw dna ecaf ym no tas yeht sa
,srotsecna eht detisiv uoY
.tem seye ruo ecnis gnidliub neeb dah noitseuq ehT
xes emas eht saw sretto neila eht fo eno yreve dna hcaE .sredneg owt tub
,lwob s’urug eht otni egnahc emos werht dna mih deknaht I
,noitativni rieht detpecca yllanif I nehW
,sinoirO ateB ot kcab yaw eht nO
.nwo ym no ti revocsid ot woh nrael ot em niart dluoc yeht tub
.psarg ym rof dehctertstuo llits dnah
.esrevinu eht em wohs d’uoy
!raeY weN yppaH ,orez ,enO
.htaenrednu elcsum laever ot yawa detlem skoob ym fo ssentfos eht ,skeew revO
”!degnahc ev’uoY .woW
.em dnuora flesti derewol
.deen dluow I thguoht I gnihtyreve dekcap I ,gninrom taht
srats eht fo seirots eht em dlot eh dna
”?knub ruoy ot kcab gniog tsuj retteb leef uoy dluoW“
.engapmahc eht saw taht ebyam rO
draeh ton dah eH .uoy nees d’eh fi mih deksa dna
.rehto hcae ta snopaew evitimirp rieht dehsidnarb sexof eht sa
!esruoc fO !stirips ehT
.enilnoyxof.www
ymra ageV eht fo reenigne na fo mrofinu eht dezingocer I
.yleritne tfel neht ,debbe dworc eht
.drawkwa steg siht erofeb emoh og dluohs I
,evE s’raeY weN saw ti ,yeh tuB
eerf deppils enim sa gnihcaer sregniF
,yltcerid noitseuq ym rewsna t’ndluoc yeht taht em dlot yehT ?uoy erew erehW
.su htaeneb deyarra sroirraw ruo
.ylleb sti morf dednecsed sriats dna
.lerdnaK yb nettirw saw
.nairatlA na esaelp ot woh dna erehw em thguat ehs
.ediw era seye ruoY
.flesym gnirevoc ,dias I ”,gnihton s’tI“
etsat tsrif ym dah I dna
,werc layol a erew yehT
.uoy ekil sterref t’nerew yeht tub
,sinoirO ateB ta trop ot em tup
.eerced s’dog eht htiw eergasid ot ekil dluow sredle rehto eht fo yna fi deksa I
.em rof evod dna
,divaD ym nees uoy evaH
yawevird a ni tnorf tuo dekrap elcycib a dna
.erofeb denigami reven ev’I sgniht gnizama em wohs d’uoy
ssaltuc-orbiv nwo reh em evag ehs
.ytivargorcim eht fo esuaceb saw taht spahrep ro—
.ereht eb ot tnaw t’ndid I dna
.yldrawkwa flesruoy fo tnorf ni sregnif revelc ruoy dlof uoY .yas I
.raey fo emit siht ton tsael ta
.1-X sungyC .reruoved taerg eht saw em fo daehA
.noitacilppus ni eman ym deirc eh
pis ot denrael yllanif I
”,pihs ecaps a evah neve t’nod I“ ”.wonk I“
,tser sih koot eh elihW
.llew nwod og t’ndid noitamalcorp ehT
,ykceB ,dneirf ym saw erehT
,rehtegot tif lla yeht woh yltcaxe gnirebmemer elbuort evah llits I
tlef yeht woh gnirebmemer elbuort on evah I tub
.sregnif etaciled ,gnol dah eH“
,traeh nekorb a htiw evil ot woh
.terref eht divaD
.snogaw latem morf tat paehc dekwah slesaeW .deyarb sraC
daer esuohthgil dlo eht ta ngis ehT .uoy dewollof I
.em erofeb seenk rieht ot llef yeht ,eno sA
srotsecna ruoy fo stirips eht tem uoy erehw ,acirfA
.saw I ohw eb ot redrah ylbaborp saw ti
dnah ym koot uoY
,retsulc eht tfel eh erofeb pots tsal sih saw inadirE atE
,em revo demraws sretto eht
plug fo daetsni pis dluohs I dias dna
.gnidaoleerf rof pihs ym no moor on s’erehT“
dnah ruoy ekaT .neila
.emit ni ti thguac evah t’ndluow
eno emoceb dah I
!morf emac uoy erehw saw taht spahreP
ekatsim lanoitnetni nA
.snossel rieht ta deplug dna ytilautirips rieht ta deppis I
,evah I taht won dna
.eye ym thguac noitom A
,em rof yletanutroF
,emadaM dias ”,yrrow uoy t’noD“
.eilseL deman lrig yhs siht tem uoy erehw
,rezagrats a dna relevart a erew uoy dias uoY
.kcab enog d’uoy gnipoh tsuj
.elbarevuenam dna keels erew taht spihs gnol htiw
.ruf ym otni debrosba ti sa delgnit dna
,nrutaS fo sgnir eht ni tops elttil a ta ni deppots eW
?deksa I ,pihs ecaps ruoy s’erehW
.enoemos s'ohw enoyreve wonk uoy dna
seirots ruoy ta deppis I
.erofeb denigami neve reven ev’uoy sgniht gnizama uoy wohs ll’I“
.noisufnoc fo tnemom a was I dna
.neerg deyd saw selpmet ruoy revo ruf eht dna
sliart eulb tnecserohpsohp htiw
,niaga uoy dnuof I dalg m’I
sbmuht tuohtiw xof a s’eH
,dlog fo seciov dna wolley fo srehtaef htiw seiranac erew sevals wollef yM
.wollof ot regae oot lla saw I
ylhtooms os rehtegot dednelb yeht litnu
?eh si erehw nehT“
,dias yeht ,nevaeh morf nellaf ,dog a saw I
”uoY dniF oT“ saw sihT
.tneps saw I .tuo nrow saw I
.nwo ruoy no elpoep ecaf ot tfel dna tuo deggard gnieb
yromem etirovaf sih tpek
,em htiw emoC .sdneirf ym
.enots dilos hguorht tropelet ot woh dna
.dlrow ym fo seirots llet em raeh ot derehtag yehT
.ksam a dah eh dias eH“
sregnif suoiruc dna
.sreltna ym ni delgnat sgel reh ,noissap reh nI
.etsopir eht dna bats ehT
,diotenalp gnirednaw llams a detibro ylizal ew sA
,eciton morf edih ot snoom eht fo wodahs eht otni welf ew nehw dna
erafraw lanoitnevnocnu fo snoitareneg sseltnuoc eht dah t’ndah yeht tub
,flesreh niatpac ehT
.slriws eulb gniwolg ym edih ot ebor nwo ym em evag dna
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,dias eh ”,ereh ton si kees uoy ohw eH“
.ytic emaceb tropriA
sdnah ym koot yehT
,snonnac resal eht fo lerrab eht gninaelc krow ot tup saw I
.ega ni gnidnecsed htuoy fo edirp eht ekil
.yllaer ,tluaf nwo ym saw tI .t’ndah uoY
sexof ym nopu nwod dekool I
”?thgin taht em dlot uoy tahw rebmemer uoy oD“
.hguone neeb dah enO
”.og gnittel reve terger I won dna ,mih tsol I tub
,dnim ni ylmrif noitanitsed dna
epor a yb em dleh ediug ym tub
,smra nepo htiw em deteerg yeht
.yllaretil dna
aluben eht fo sdaerht cilohocla eht hguorht meht htiw gnitrovac keew dnoces ym yb dna
.deleehwtrac pihs ym sa nups thgiE ageV tenalp ehT
.gnippis naht rehtar gniplug neeb d’I nehw
.elihw a rof meht htiw yalp em edab dna
---   lerdnaK yb ”uoY dniF oT“
.eilseL s'ti uoy dlot I dna
”,hsiloof eb t’noD“
,evael ym gnikat eb dluow I taht decnuonna I nehW
.wen gnihtemos em dewohs uoy sa
efink a werd sredle eht fo enO
,pirg ym elots dworc eht tub ,deirt yllaer I
.del teef drawyaw reverehw demaor uoy sa dias uoy
,sexof ynnac erew yehT
.dias I ”.esruoc fO“
,devirra elttab eht fo yad eht emit eht yb dna
.ruf rieht otni deyd
.siht tnaw t’ndid I
:nrael dluoc selamef ylno taht scigam neddibrof eerht eht em thguat yehT
rumel esiw a tem I niatnuom eht fo pot eht tA
”.ton m’I ,esruoc fo tuB“
.dlrow eht em wohs ll’uoy dna uoy wolloF
sreksihw gnilkcit htiw
,sdamon nairutcrA eht morf hcum denrael I elihw dna
”?srepsalc deromra ruoy era erehw tuB“
.snairyL ateB eht htiw raw rieht otni dellup neeb yllatnedicca
,dne tsum smaerd lla tuB
,llits uoy llems nac I .ereht erew uoy
dna eno siht piks nac uoy
,semahT eht fo erohs eht ta flesym dnuof I
.hguorht ssap terref nedlog a nees dah enoyna fi deksa I erehw
?dedaj gnimoceb I saW
.reisae setarip eht gnoma emit ym edam ti ,gnihtyna fI
.rewohs a desu evah yllaer dluoc sseddog rieht
.selacs ni derevoc erew taht sregnif htiw daeh ym detfil eH
sreltna ym gnippirg erew uoy dna ,owt ,eerht ,ruoF
eros saw eugnot ym litnu pu em wolla t’ndid ehS
sdamon gniraf-ecaps fo ecar a fo draeh I nehw
,kcen ym dnuora ralloc a dekcol rethgierf eht ,devirra ew nehW
.uoy nees d’eh esruoc fo
.elbaulav tsom dna
.sdalas dlos stnaruatser taht mih llet ot traeh eht ton dah I
.ruf ym tsniaga gnibbur ailatineg elamef/elam denibmoc dna
.sepor on erew ereht taht tcaf eht htiw gnitrats
timda tsum I tub ,noitarbelec eht nioj ot dednetni t’ndah I
.yks eht til hsalf cimsylcatac a
ekatsim a s'ti taht dias uoY
.ydob ym degnahc dah sretto dna elttab dna yrevals yaw eht noitnem ot ton
.gninrom eht ni ruof saw tI
.ebirt rieht fo retsis a saw I taht wohs ot
reesrevo eht fo htarw eht ward dluow
,dog dehsilpmocca na ehs saw ylno ton
.tsurtsid htiw em ta deralg seye ruof hcihw morf ecaf a demarf hcihw
neesnu ecruos a morf ylleb ym ssorca detriuqs diuqil toH
”?neila na erew uoy yas uoy
.uoy fo riah ron edih draeh ton dah llits I
ograc elbaulav htiw srethgierf esiwnu dezirorret ew
.ytic eht ni erehwyna og dluoc ew erehw dnuorgrednu eht otni nwod
meht ot degluvid I ,ecnedifnoc nI
er’yehT .setarip eht tuoba yrrow t’noD
,enim thguac seye ruoY
,snroh delruc sih revo depoord taht srae gnol htiw
surutcrA nus eht litnu ydob ym detarbelec yehT
,yawa-wots ecaps a sa denrael dah I slliks eht mih gniwohs dehsinif dah I nehw dna
,ria rof gniplug em dah daeh ym ni gnizzub ehT
,tirips a saw eh fi mih deksa I
,tuo stenalp wef a uoy teg nac I“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.gnitaeper no dednetni uoy eno t'nsaw ti dna
,deretnilps noom a sa egral sa thguandaerd A
.rood eht esolc uoy dnA
.tluaf rieht t’nsaw ti
,elppus dna egral erew selacs elprup reh ydob reh ssorcA
em gniees rof uoy knaht tub
sdog eht yb desselb ton saw raw siht taht nemo na saw
,eman ym deksa uoY
riaper pihsrats fo sregnad eht no esitaert a ”,uoY dniF oT“
.noitseuq elgnis a rof nruter ni—
,neila na eb ot demialc neve uoY
,em nihtiw delruc srebmem elisneherp rieht sa
,ksam yterref ruoy evah llits uoY
.gnihtyalp wen a dekcip dah niatpac eht taht gnirepsihw eht draeh I