.mih ta regnif a deggaw ehS ".gnifeirb
.seog ti woh s'taht ,kcehc ruoy tnaw uoy fi ,osla ,oS"
.erus ,haeY" .denaorg kciR ".mih
.thgir yletelpmoc ti teg ylbissop t'nac uoY
.thguoht ni daeh sih gnikcoc
.ni deklaw enoemos nehw ,rehtruf eraperp ot deen a naht gnihtemos od ot deen a fo tuo erom
.raelc tub ,detnecca ylivaeh saw hsilgnE s'krelc ehT
.tohs a ti evig ,esac yna nI
.reporp noitats eht otni
.lwob sih ta detrats eH ".ecaf
.rellatS .rM ,yaw sihT"
:revo dlrow eht yldliw oot yrav ot mees t'ndid srab tsafkaerb letoh tub
"-- nam dlo eht dna ,emit elohw eht tnelis ylraen erew yehT
sda elbigelli ylegral dna railimafnu sti htiw
,krow ot demees ti ,trap tsom eht roF
.egnellahc a saw tsafkaerB
si muesuM lanoitaN oykoT
.stirips retteb ni kciR dnuof gninroM".dal dooG"
.emit htfif eht rof liame kcehc ot sseleriw s'letoh eht gnisu dna emit gnillik
:railimafnu erew meht fo ynam os taht saw
etius tnemeganam dna noitatnemucod krowten cimanyd a depoleved sah snoituloS rellatS
.thgir etiuq dellems gnihton tub
.pots sih ta mroftalp eht otno dellepxe saw eh sa
,railimafnu yllohw regnol on saw deb ehT
,tuo emac gnihton dna tnemom a rof niarb sih dekcar eh tub
.yawbus eht no dworc gninrom eht htiw dnetnoc ot dah eh os
ksed eht ot pu deppets eh sa daeh sih dekcud kciR
.pam a ta kool dna dnats ot secaps fo tol a eb ot mees t'ndid ereht
.dlof eht otni uoy thguorb ew erofeb reerac a dah uoy ,sediseB
.etabed rof pu ton saw siht dias taht kool a mih evag anoiF ".esaelp ,adekI .rM"
".yllarutaN" .deddon eH
.esrow od dluoc uoY
,moor eht fo tsom pu koot deb ehT
.roirp sraey lareves derih neeb d'ehs ecnis reh fo ylhgih nekops dah rehtaf siH
,tuo flesmih dehsurb dna nwod deppirts eH
.esle enoemos gnittih tuohtiw eganam dluoc eh sa wob a fo hcum sa ni daeh sih gnikcud dna
.yek moor a yb denioj ,noihsaf emas eht ni denruter saw drac eht neht dna ,gnipyt eroM
".od ot esle gnihtyna evah t'ndid yllaer I dna ,ekat dluow ti gnol woh wonk t'ndid I
,tekcop tnorf sih ni ti dnuof eh ,yllaniF
,yaw gnol a uoy teg ll'tahT
,elbat eht no nwo reh fo potpal a tes ehS ".esaelp ,anoiF"
.tellaw sih rof dehcaer dna deddon kciR ".uoy
.ot desu saw eh seno eht naht retrohs ylraelc saw deb siht tub
.saw eh naht retrohs tol a llits dna ,reitniop elttil a ,regral ,renaeL
,teiuq a ni gnieB
.enohp reh no kcolc eht ta decnalg dna desuap ehS ".yzarc
"?pu dewercs yllaer I esle gnihtynA
.kool prahs a htiw mih dexif ehS ".esnepxe
.edis rehto eht ot daeh sih denrut kciR ".ynapmoc
deredro dah anoiF
.daeh sih dekcud kciR ".usamiazog otagirA" .niaga dewob krelc ehT ".sknaht ,oN"
fo tros eht htiw nexiv a saw eralC'O anoiF
.rood eht ta redluohs sih revo dekool neht
,laem sih htiw dehsiniF
.elpmet eht ni regnessap rehtona dekcolc dna
"!mM" .regnuh rof moor ekam ot detaerter noisnet eht dna
.elims elttil a deirt eH
.niaga deggurhs ehS ".derc
.deggurhs neht ,tnemom a rof taht detalpmetnoc ehS ".evif
sriats eht fo pot eht ta degreme eh dna mih htiw saw kcuL
.od nac su fo yna lla s'tahT"
,ksed eht no ti pord ot tuo potpal sih dehsif dna
.noos tuo gnikcehc saw tibah taht deyojne tseug revetahw depoh eh dna ,ekoms etteragic fo dekeer ecaps eht ,yletanutrofnU
.noitatneserp elohw eht hguorht luof gnihtemos dellems d'eh ekil dekool adekI .rM ,kO"
,delebal ton elihw ,dna ,ybraen erew ragus dna maerC
.eno taht fo dnof syawla saw daD
.fo trap a ton ylraelc saw eh erutluc a rof
elbat eht fo edis rehto eht no doots yehT
,gniteem eht retfa stif mih gnivig saw hcamots sih dna ,egnarts dellems dna dekool tI ".lwob
.nalp atad on dna ,haeY"
.gnitaes enilria ymonoce ot noissecnoc a
.enohp eht debbarg dna dehgis ehS ".SU
,etunim a rof gnipiws dna gnippat suoiruf eroM ".ti od ll'I ,eniF"
.ffo gnitteg elpoep etadommocca ot no kcab pmuj dna evael
.mih tuoba gnihtemos tsuj s'tI
;pu tes teg s'tel ,woN
ngis a tsniaga flesmih gnikcut ,yawa kaerb ot deganam eH
.pu ti xim ot uoy dlot I yhw s'tahT"
.ti eldnah ll'I ,oN" .wap a tuo dleh dna
deyalpsid ylegral sngis daehrevO
syawssorc peels ot yaw a dnif ot deganam eh ,dnuora gnissuf emos retfA
.yltcefrep nam eht
.taht ekil gnihtemos ro gninaemed ssel s'ti
.mmmH" ".tsafkaerb hsilpmocca ot deganam ylerab I
.kciR ot kcab noitnetta reh denrut anoiF
.esle gnihtyreve did ehs ytisnetni gniyfirret-tsomla
.etummoc eht rof leef a teg ot gnitrats m'I"
,rehtona ni sehsid dna syart ,aera eno ni doof saw ereht
,srood eht hguorht ylsseldne ruop ot demees sega lla fo sdik loohcs dna ,nemow ,neM
.ecneirepxe eht rof tsuj ,ti yrt ot devloser kciR dna
.yawa ti tup dna ti ecnelis ,kO"
.uoy rof gnitiaw ydaerla si eralC'O .sM
.nevig neeb dah kciR oib eht dehctam osla neR abA
.gninethgiarts dedeen ti taht ton
elzzum sih otni 'lwob ykcits' fo lufnoops rehtona delevohs kciR ".sekatsim
.mih dnuora gnihtyreve fo devorppasid eh hguoht sa
.esion dnuorgkcab fo tros a otni
.htrow s'ti naht elbuort erom s'taht dna ,tisiv uoy noiger yreve rof enohp a uoy teg ro taht s'tI .hE" .erutseg eugav a ni swap reh delggaw dna deggurhs anoiF
.noitapucco ,sbmob raelcun ,spmac tnemnretni ,raW"
.noos oot hcum oot saw siht rehtaf ruoy dlot I"
.detnioppasid eb ot detcepxe ylpmis eh spahreP
.noisnet gniworg a dima trofmoc fo tops llams a saw ti
.hguone doog saw taht dna ,eeffoc saw ti tub ,tluser eht ni ecnereffid eht llet t'ndluoc eH
,tnatsissa evitucexe s'rehtaf sih gniteem eb d'eh dias liamE
.ylsuoiruc nexiv eht deye dna
.kcab srae sih gninnip kciR tfel segaugnal railimafnu fo nid eht dna ,hsilgnE gnikaeps saw aera gninid eht ni ydoboN
.tekcop sih ni enohp sih deffuts dna teef sih ot delbmarcs kciR
.lla retfa ,nrael dluoc eh spahreP
,eno ta detniop eH
railimaf erom elttil a saw roiretni eht dna
,eciffo 'stneilc eht ot ecnatsid gniklaw elbanosaer a ton saw letoh ehT
dedaf tser eht litnu
.tneilc rieht yb dewollof ,hguorht deppets reilrae morf tsinoitpecer eht dna denepo rood eht sa
,tuo daerps ot moor erom elttil a dah sdworc eht tub ,sllems hserf fo tes nwo sti dedda
.ecnedifnoc hcuS" .detrons ehS ".erus
.tuo ti yrt ot tsuj
.hsif dellirg fo dnik emos rof segasuas railimaf eht tuo dedart d'yeht sa
,dias ,wob elttil a evag revres ehT ".usamihsiageno
,enohp ruoy desu evah dluoc uoy ,wonk uoY"
.ssecorp eht hguorht mih pleh ot hsilgnE hguone ekops stekcit gnikat nexiv eht ,yletanutroF
hcum reggats t'ndid eh tnaem
,sthgil eht tuc yllufpleh anoiF ".og
"?thgir ,taht tuoba nrael did uoY .yrotsih ruo ni strap ypmub wef a era erehT
.ylhtooms gninnur ti gnipeek sruoh nam ynam oot yleritne demusnoc taht
.mih nioj ot deirt esle ydobon ,yletanutroF
,hcum oot yleritne saw tI
.tnuocca ynapmoc a no si moor ruoy ees I .ris sey ,iah
.flow fo tros kcolc-o-neves a neeb syawla d'eh ecnis
.ylimaf gnirih fo egatnavda ehT" .deggurhs ehS ".rehtegot
.rM .taht ot rewsna eht wonk uoy kniht I"
.devirra d'eh ecnis tniop emos ta enihcam gnidnev a no dnarb eht nees d'eh erus ytterp saw eH
,gniliec eht ta derats eh ,daetsnI
.esnepxe devorppa na s'tI
.srae sih dekcilf kciR
;seirtsudnI yvaeH adekI rof ygolonhceT noitamrofnI fo PV eht saw adekI .rM
.og ew sa gnicnerefer eb ll'I taht erawtfos eht tuoba sliated erom sniatnoc tI
.esolc saw ti tub ,ni neeb d'eh rotavele tsellams eht t'nsaw ti
".su fo daeha krow fo tol a evah ew
.ffuts ruoy rof srevom dnes ylbaborp dluohs ew ,haeY ...naem I ?ew diD .mmH" .elbat eht no walc a deppat ehS
"?ekatsim a ekam I fi dnA"
,tekcap a tneilc eht evig uoy emit txeN"
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,enohp sih ta dekcilf dna
,ylrae ylsuoicalleh eb ot gniog saw eH
"?uoy rof detacilpmoc oot ,doof tae ,tekcit tneserP
.gnola wollof ot ekil d'uoy fi ,noitatneserp eht fo ypoc detatonna na si tahT" .rehto eht neht
.neht yb dehsinif htob d'yehT ".hguone
.elpoep evlewt naht rewef on gnicneinevnocni retfa ekatsim sih tcerroc ot gniganam tub
,mih ta delims krelc daeh ehT ".uoy knaht ,hU"
.srenretsew tsniaga yllaicepse
.gnillif dna elbatalap htob ti dnuof eh
.meht fo tuo erom teg dna
trap eno dna ,railimaf trap eno saw doof ehT
.ciffart fo wolf eht tsniaga sriats eht pu kcab yaw sih ekam ot dah eh dna
daeh reh koohs ehS
eht no esacfeirb reh tup dna mih ot txen taes eht koot ehS ".ylrae er'uoy ,kciR"
.aedi on evah I dnA
tsuj t'nsaw noitcaer s'adekI
.mlap reh fo edis eht ot esolc dleh bmuht reh dna
.uoy eciton ot meht rof gnitiaw dnuora tis t'noD
,od ot krow emos evah I"
,yad rehtona rof tpels evah dluoc eh ekil tlef eH
.deb eht fo egde eht ffo delgnad swap sih
.daeh reh koohs ehS
.retupmoc eht no gnipyt detrats dna tropssap sih ta neht
.tellaw sih dnuof eh litnu stnap sih nwod dettap dna tuhs elzzum sih deppalc neht ,deffuh eH ".iaH .seY .haeY"
sserttam eht no flesmih fo lla teg dna
,hA" .saw mih tuoba gnihtyreve ekil tlef eH
,tnemom a rof reh deye kciR ".spaM
,anagarih dna ijnak fo xim gnitartsurf a
.esenapaJ eb ot demees spuorg ynam dna ,esenihC neeb evah thgim rehtona
.did ecnaraeppa sih naht erom raf
"?slatnedicni rof drac a evah uoy oD
.swap htob ni yart eht pu dekcip eh sa wob elttil a evag dna delims krelc ehT
,oot ,elpoep era esenapaJ eht ,taht enigami ,oS
-- snoitcerid tisnart eht gniziromem emit hcum os tneps d'eh lufetarg saw eH
ehS ".siht ekil ,wap elohw ruoy esu ot etilop erom s'ti tub
"?thgir ,no ti nrut ot woh wonk od uoY"
.srae reh dekcilf dna deggurhs ehS ".secivres
.yadretsey naht retal er'uoy ,sediseB
,niart eht fo tuo dna ni deruop elpoeP
.dab kool em gnikam erew uoY"
.denepo srood eht nehw sregnessap rehto eht htiw no delffuhs eh dna
si yrots s’yadot dna
.dnif ot detcepxe eh tahw hcum ytterp dah ti lla ni tub
ytic eht fo ria nepo ehT
seidob fo hsurc eht taht gninil revlis a saw tI
,saw letoh eht sa yldneirf sA .deganam eh
a ni noops sih devaw kciR ".yaw
.gab sih morf noitatneserp dna potpal sih tuo dellup dna deggurhs eH ".yadretsey
,elbat eht ssorca drac sih edils ot detrats eH
,sevren sih deidaets eeffoC
,gut a tekcaj reh evag dna ecivda nwo reh dewollof ehS ".pu
,niaga deggurhs anoiF ".dooG"
.ma I kniht I ,wonk uoY"
ereht ffo gnitteg sredir eht fo tser eht htiw dellepxe saw eh ,pots sih ta devirra niart eht emit eht yb dna
,lanoitidart ylbirret t'nsaw ti erus saw eH
.gnimlehwrevo ssel tub
.teiuq ylgnisirprus saw niart ehT
.mih ta dennirg anoiF
ot desu saw eh tahw morf tnereffid tol a saw ti tub
.worbeye na desiar ehS
,sekatsim ekam ll'uoy ,hO"
.rehtegot tog ew emit yna ti tuoba klat ot devol daD esuaceb yltsoM"
.gnifeirb larutluc ym eb lliw siht sseug I
.srood eht revo ngis eht no pu deppop dedeen eh noitats eht fo eman eht ,yllautnevE
,gnusmaS ro ijuF sa tnaig fo tros emas eht t'nsaw IHI
gniliec eht morf gnignah sngis eht nacs ot thgieh sih fo egatnavda lluf koot eH
tsuj I ;deirt t'nevah I"
,irauR nosmirC yb
;egaggul sih htiw ecaps eht otni flesmih egdew ot deganam dna rotavele eht ot dereggats eH ".otagirA"
,retal snrut gnorw lareves dna klaw trohs A
.redluohs sih dettap anoiF ".seog
.og uoy ereht tub
,mih ot wen saw noitanibmoc eht elihw dna ,sgge delbmarcs niht dna
doog dellems ti ,sulP
,thgir eht ton ,tfel eht no klaw ot gnittegrof
thguoht fo enil siht morf detcartsid saw kciR
.ti dnuora ylbatrofmoc klaw dluoc eh tub
daehrevo morf gnignah eldnah a rof dehcaer eH
.ereht ecnedifnoc fo etov taerG"
?gniyrt ylerecniS ?gniyrt era uoy taht tuB
.gninrom eht fo tser eht morf egnahc tnasaelp a saw flesmih rof dedeen eh naht regral saw taht ecaps ytpme
"?ris ,uoy rof od nac ew esle gnihtyna ereht sI
.hguone riaF" .niaga deddon eH ".refsnart
.depmarc t'nsaw ti
.stnemom wef a rof ylsuoiruf ti ta yawa deppat dna potpal reh denepo ehS "?yllaeR"
.htob ro ecaf eht ni enoemos gniwoble ro ti gnippord tuohtiw tuo ti teg d'eh erus t'nsaw eh dna ,tekcop a ni dekcut saw ti tub
.ney dnasuoht elpuoc a ylno dna suoegrog
mih ot tsesolc stnecs esoht tsuj no desucof eh os
.lausac ytterp s'ti ,neht neve tub
.seog ti woh ees ll'ew dna tseb ym ti evig ll'I ,tsael eht tA
,reh ta dekool dna snoitaraperp sih desuap kciR
,mih ta pu decnalg krelc ehT ".rellatS
.yaw emas eht era ohw SU eht ni kcab sklof tem ev'uoy erus m'I" .dennirg ehS ".srenretsew
dworc eht htiw evom ssel ro erom ot deganam eh dna ,enoyna tih t'ndid eh tub
.esacfeirb sih barg dna
.ereh gnitteg dna ,tsafkaerb ,nur gninrom a rof emit fo ytnelp
,ikunat a saw eh tnaem siht ,esac sih nI
,dias trahc gro eht revetahW
.kO" .deddon kciR ".etilop
.dniheb tfel tog ydobon levram a saw tI
,ysae mees ti edam slacoL
.detnioppasid skool eh ,nees reve ev'I otohp yrevE
.daeh sih koohs eH
.noitcerid thgir eht ni dael ot demees taht mroftalp a no doots eh ,hguone nooS
edis eno ot tesolc nepo ,llams a saw erehT
",emit siht ereh em taeb uoY"
.taht ekil skool syawla eh esuaceb taht ekil dekool adekI .rM oS"
.noitisop gnipeels elbatrofmoc erom a dnif ot deganam d'eh dna
,flow yerg llat a
,htrow s'yad a neve ,ecitcarP
,secidujerp revotfel evah ,seilimaf od-ot-llew erom morf yllaicepse ,ereh sklof redlo fo tol a ,seY
.retteb enog evah dluoc taht ,oS"
.gninrom eht ni pu gnikaw saw dna
".ereh
,lleH .ti rof gnihtyna kcap t'ndid I dna
gnildnah ria ta tpmetta yna demlehwrevo niart eht no elpoep fo ytisned reehs ehT
,niaga nwo sih no saw eh ereht morF
.hsilgnE ssel hcum ,ijnamoR ni delebal erew snoitpo eht fo enon
.ybbol s'adekI deretne eh sa ksed noitpecer eht dniheb netram eht ot deddon eH
.eno thgir eht saw ti erus ylriaf saw eh ,devirra niart a emit eht yb dna ,ijnamor hguorht detator osla yeht tub
.lufsserts ssel elttil a dna
.noitats eht morf kcolb tneinevnoc yrev a saw eciffo seirtsudnI yvaeH adekI ehT
.usamihsiageno ,ukkehC" "?iaH"
,dedworc elihw ,taht syawbus naeporuE neve dna naciremA no neeb d'eh
"?srenretsew tsniaga gniht a evah eh seoD ?won tahW"
,dedworc saw ti ,steerts eht no tuO
.seog efil woh s'tI
.SU eht tfel I erofeb secivres llec ffo denrut
.ni yltsom hguoht
.dluoc eh tseb sa tsafkaerb hguorht delddum kciR
,tneiciffe-ecaps dna llams elihw ,taht desirprus yltnasaelp saw dna
,tekcit sih dah eh ecno ,nehT
.spaM dna etalsnarT hguorht uoy teg dluohs ti ,llitS
.regnol yna letoh eht ni tis ot raeb t'ndluoc eh tub
.esu ot reisae elttil a tsuj saw moorhtab ehT
.setag fo tes thgir eht hguorht tuo og ot wolf ciffart eht morf kaerb ot deganam dna
.ytsat etiuq osla dna ykcits etiuq deedni saw tI
.ynapmoc nretsew a er'ew taht pleh t'nseod ylbaborp ti ,hguohtlA"
.hE" .dnatsrednu t'ndluoc kciR msaisuhtne na htiw lwob reh otni dekcut dna deggurhs anoiF
.no llits saw net ta gninrom taht gniteem eht detseggus radnelac siH
.yaw taht ti fo kniht ,sey tuB
.sgod nooccar tub ,snooccar t'nerew yeht taht dezilaer kciR dna
.daer dluoc eh egaugnal a ni delebal saw aera tnaruatser eht ni elttil yrev
.detnirp s'ti tnemom eht etad fo tuo si
kniht I ;dlot saw I tahw s'tI
.emit elbanosaer a etiuq yllaer s'tahT"
ot dah sredir woh nevig ,rood eht raen ton saw eh dalg saw eH
egaggul sih dehsats eH
.stnecs fo ynohpocac a saw niart ehT
.dennirg nexiv ehT .dekramer eh
,tekcit tsafkaerb sih derebmemer eH .yaw gnol a tnew
dworc eritne eht dna ,gnisolc erew srood eht sa tsuj
,letoh sih ot teg ot sniart elpitlum gnikat neht dna ,drac niart a gnitteg
".os sseug I haeY .haeY"
.desu d'eh smoor naciremA tsom fo ecaps fo setsaw evissam eht fo enon htiw ,letoh a fo tuo detcepxe eh gnihtyreve dah ti ,lla nI
,evreser htiw flesmih deirrac ohw xof derruf-revlis gnihtemos-ytfif a saw atuoS adekI
.meht htiw sllems ynam os ro elpoep ynam os evah t'ndid
.noitanitsed sih ot dael ylbaborp dluow mih fo tnorf ni sriats eht taht gnidiced yllanif ,sgniraeb sih teg ot ecnahc eht koot dna
.dedeen eh enil eht ot dael
,elbatpecca saw siht taht ediced ot demees hcamots siH
,esruoc fo ,esenapaJ ni
doots ehs sa elims thgils a dereffo tub ,mih ta worbeye na desiar ehS ".oyahO"
".gnilles er'ew erawtfos eht wonk uoy tsael tA
.gnilles saw kciR erawtfos tnemeganam krowten eht gnitargetni rof reganam tcejorp eht eb ot saw abA .rM
krowten gnitseretni na rof ekam ot napaJ tuohguorht snoitacol noitcudorp hguone naht erom deniatniam yeht tub
?hcum sa dias tsuj eh t'ndaH .ton yleruS
no mih nevig dah rehtaf sih weivrevo dna otohp eht dehctam eH
,nur ot epahs on ni saw I" .detrons kciR ".esrow
.hcamots sih ni ssenitpme gnilworg eht delttes doof eht dna
.elbat eht ssorca meht dils dna
.evah thgim eh regnuh eht gnileef t'nsaw eh os
.detrats kciR dna
"?yadot yna ekam I diD"
.ylhtooms nur dluow krowten eht depoh eH
ot ti edam I ykcul m'I .ecno ta lla ,od ot hcum oS .drac niart ,egnahcxe ,smotsuC .em dnimer t'nod ,hO" .seye sih dellor eH ".smotsuC
hsif eht htiw ti deppot dna lwob a ni ecir delip eh ,denedlobmE
.elbaeganam saw ti tub
.ylfeirb ylno tem d'eh mohw
"?yadot ti lles yllaer ot ydaeR
,regnol yna llits tis t'ndluoc eH
.hguone doog s'taht dna ,su ot gniklat s'eH
?taht kniht uoy sekam tahW"
.setag rehto eht ot mih dnuora tuc elpoep erom yna tsel ,hguorht deirruh eh os ,edisa gnuws setag eht dna neerg tnew yalpsid eht tub
.huh-hU" ".sseug I ,eruS"
pu nehserf ot moor sih ta ni deppots kciR
.yawyna ,ynapmoc eht no s'eno sihT
.sekatsim suoigerge tsom eht tneverp dluohs ti dna
.otagira" na dna
.deirt eh hcum woh rettam on ,ecaps hcum oot pu gnikat dna dworc eht fo tser eht evoba sredluohs dna daeh
".worromot pu wercs ot ton yrt dna gninrael emos od og ,woN
.retteb hcum t'nsaw pots txen ehT
-- doof dilos eht rof dalg flesmih dnuof eH
ssob sih morf trapa mih tes taht ygrene elbatrofmocnu na dah dna
,gniticxe erom neve saw flesti tsafkaerb dna
,wap a devaw ehs ",ylknarf ,sulP
.ereht drac sih tup neht
,naivanidnacS ro namreG eb thgim yeht ekil dednuos eno
.tniop ym ot kcab em sgnirb taht dnA"
:elpicnirp gnidiug elpmis a dnuora tliub
"nesamimus" gnitrulb rof delttes eh os
.driht a ni noitats aet dna eeffoc a dna
.otagirA" .deddon kciR ".uoy
.rehtie ,slegna t'nerew ylbaborp yeht tub ,elpoep dab ekil demees reven d'yehT
.lwob ykcits" a saw ti mih dlot dna
.mih fo tnorf ni tas taht esle gnihtemos dna hsif dna ecir fo lwob eht ta debbats kciR ".retteb
"?tuoba taht s'tahW"
.noissimda fo tros gnilffaw
".kniht uoy naht retteb gniod er'uoY
".hguone llew tnew tI
.driew elttil a tlef roolf desiar sti tub
.ton ro suoires saw nwod tas ehs sa mih evag ehs kool detnioppasid eht fi llet t'ndluoc eH ".noos
,depmarc llits saw eciffo adekI eht ot edir ehT
.yzarc og t'nod uoy fi ,slaem ruoy fo tser eht era sA
.rood eht hguorht atuoS dewollof rof gnitiaw erew yeht nosrep rehto eht nehw
.deraeppa liam weN
.egassap efas fo namsilat a erew ti hguoht sa "nesamimus" gnilbmum
.moorhtab eht tuo kcehc ot tnew neht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,irauR nosmirC yb ”noisneT oykoT“
.trats a saw taht dna
".letoh eht
"?ti etavitca ot yrt uoy diD .ti deredro eW"
.retrohs elttil a dna ssob sih naht dliub reikcots tahwemos fo
,smotsuc hguorht gnitteg ,enalp a no sruoh evlewt retfA
.erutluc rieht ni dnuora gnitaolf seussi ralimis evah yeht dna
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ylrae na otni mih tup eugitaf levart tel dna
.noci liam eht dekop neht
.setag eht hguorht yltnedifnoc gniklaw dna redaer eht tsniaga sdrac rieht ro senohp rieht gnittup
.etilop s'ti tub ,snoitcaer rieht ni ecnereffid a eciton t'now ylbaborp uoY
.noitats niart eht ta flesmih dnuof kciR
.smotsuC ta romuh fo esnes ruoy tfel evah tsum uoY .ekoj a s'tI"
,erawtfos fo eceip taerg a lles eW
.nalp detimilnu eht uoy teg t'ndid eW .soediv tac ynam oot hctaw t'noD .ereH"
.6032 eb lliw moor ruoY"
"?ew did ,siht erofeb gnifeirb erutluc a uoy evig t'ndid ew sseug I .llew ,seY" ".hO"
.rellatS kciR .moor a evah I"
.cibohportsualc werg seidob fo sserp eht dna
ni dezeeuqs tacssenisub enO
,seY .cipot no kcaB"
”noisneT oykoT“ saw sihT
wob trohs a evag ehS ".otagirA"
".erutluc rieht tcepser ot gniyrt er'uoy meht wohS .sgniht fo elpuoc a gnignahc yrT .eniF"
-- tluciffid erom saw eeffoC
.evif ta pu saw I .on doG"
.ylwols oot yleritne gnivom saw eh taht raelc saw ti tub ,gnihtyna dias eno oN
.etal etunim a naht ylrae ruoh na retteB .eralC'O .sM" .riahc
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no ro ,stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw su dnif nac uoy
.doof sih fo etib a koot eH ".noitatneserp
.nwod gab sih tes dna
,emit elbanosaer a ta pu gnikaw no ssergorp laer saw kcolc'o xiS
".noitatnemucoD ehT sI krowteN ehT
.refsnart eht egdelwonkcA
,enohp sih rof gnihcaer tuoba thguoht kciR
dessap gniyrrow rof emit ehT
,hguone ylidaer ti dnuof eh os ,devom t'ndah noitats yawbus ehT
.edis tcerroc eht no neeb d'eh tsael tA
".gniht regnif eht fo luofa nur t'nseod tub ,esicerp sa tsuJ"
,railimaf saw hcuM
esacfeirb sih fo tuo sredlof fo elpuoc a dehsif kciR ".su
.elpoep fo wolf eht htiw pu tpews dna
.mih ta noops reh delevel ehS ".og
irauR nosmirC yb
,sediseB" .deggurhs eH ".eno
.troppus dilos emos detnaw kciR
.tropssap sih revo dessap kciR
.ti raeh ot dooG" .deddon ehS ".etummoc
.nisuoc a saw OEC eht
.sgge ynnur-ylthgils eht dna
elbat eht morf elttil a kcab dehsup anoiF
.niaga mih ta pu dekool krelc ehT
,meht sdrawot delffuhs eH
.tnereffid erew slacimehc gninaelc eht neve
.daetsni ,nirg a mih evag dna
.hcnul s'yad suoiverp eht fo mih dednimer dna
,devirra ti nehw dedworc ydaerla saw niart ehT
,ereh ti od slacol ees ll'uoy ,eruS
.gnihtemos ro muesum a ees og dluohs uoy tub
.ecaf pmurg gnitser
,skrelc eht rof thgieh-tsehc saw tI
.od dluoc eh tsael eht saw ssenetilop elttil A ".otagira"
-- secneirepxe roirp s'kciR fo yna dedeecxe ylhguoroht ti dna
.kcolc'o evif ta ekawa flesmih dnuof kciR.peels yvaeh
:spuorg tcnitsid ni deretsulc ohw ,srenid eht fo tser eht fo erawa emaceb eh
,steid rieht ni sdoof tnereffid ,spaos 'sredir ni slacimehc tnereffid
.ti htiw od ot yltcaxe tahw wonk t'ndid eh
!eciN" .dehgual anoiF
,llat oot elttil a gnieb ot desu nettog d'eh ,owt-toof-xis tA
41 taeH ni seirots trohs sah ohw
,ytic eht otni raf siht
.stroffe latnemunom emoceb dah sksat elpmis neve
.srood eht tsniaga desserp mih tfel ti hguoht
walc a fo pit eht htiw mra eht ni mih debbaj ehS ".ereht
.mih ta kcab ti tsurht ehs neht
,ot desu saw eh naht retrohs saw but ehT
.mih ta dennirg anoiF ".hhhhhU"
,thgin taht fo esnes ekam dna yrt ot gniog neve ton saw eh hcihw ,lenap lortnoc a dah teliot eht dna
,hcnul tsrif rieht htiw ottan tae t'ndluow snaciremA tsoM
.tuo now ytniatrecnu tub ,etunim a rof derewsnanu og ti tel eH
moor eht ot ti edam eH
.reh ta daeh sih dekcoc eH "?hE"
.hhhhhU" ".emoh teg uoy erofeb devom uoy evah dluoc eW ?tuo gnissarrabme gnihtyna toG
rood eht morf rehtraf dna rehtraf delffuhs gnitteg flesmih dnuof eh litnu eueuq eht fo elddim eht ni ylno saw eh dezilaer ton dah eH
.eeffoc htiw puc sih dellif yllautneve dna delworg dna derrihw enihcam ehT .snottub eht fo eno gnisserp rof delttes eH
.neeb dah ydaerla eh spahreP
.regnif eno htiw tniop t'nod
.enihcam eht no nottub rehto eht desserp eh
.deddon anoiF ".ko ,iaH"
xim eht ot gniddA
,ylroop nesohc dah eh taht delaever mroftalp taht no sniart eht fo noitcepsni resolc ,yletanutrofnU
,nwod sriats fo tes eno dewollof eh ,hguorht ecnO
saw taht sucof gnisitrevda rieht dna
seirots erom roF
.evil ot tnaw uoy fi niaga ma'am em llac reve t'noD"
.niaga nepo d'yeht fi derednow kciR
.adekI .rM s'tahT .oS"
.secivres ruo stnaw eh ton ro rehtehw htiw od ot gnihton sah tahT
liame devas a tlusnoc ot dah llits eh tub ,drac eraf sih dah ydaerla eH
,sesirprus rojam on erew erehT
.dellacer eh ,ikunaT
,snoitasrevnoc dah sredir wef A
,tuo doots eh wenk eH
.koob a yub ebyam ,erutluc eht tuoba elttil a nrael ,oG
”noisneT oykoT“:yojne esaelP
rehtegot sregnif ruof lla htiw lwob sih ta derutseg
.ti ta dekop dna tuo enohp sih dellup eH
.lwob sih fo sniamer eht otni gniggid yb gnirewsna dediova dna delbmurg kciR ".dlof
.ekil saw ruoh hsur oykoT a tahw rof deraperp ton saw kciR
,SU eht ni skrow adnik tahT .elbat eht no ti ssot tsuj ot ton yrt
,wap nepo-ylralimis a htiw reh ta kcab detniop eH
sruoh nam eht ecuder IHI pleh dluow tcudorp s'kciR
.reh htiw eugra ot naht retteb wenk eh
.gib oot elttil a neeb evah thgim elims sih ekil tlef kciR
,deb otni llef eh nehW
,gnimrahc ylbidercni dnuof eh taht tnecca hsirI detum
.tnatsissa evitucexe s'rehtaf sih saw ,esac siht ni ,enoemos tahT
.noitpo na t'nsaw ni gnipeels esoppus I"
.derc teerts emos evah uoy ,dias I ekiL"
.revres a ta devaw dna
.em dlot ydoboN .on ,hA"
.ma'am ,seY" .delkcuhc kciR ".koob
.ni delip elpoep erom sa
.nosinu ni dewob ksed tnorf eht dniheb snooccar owt ehT
"?evisnepxe ylsuoedih ti t'nsI
".snoitcnuf noitagivan eseht sah ti raeh I
.deednI" ".doog skooL"
.rof gnikool saw ehs tahw yltcaxe dnuof ehs ylkciuq woh tsuj ta desserpmi saw kciR
desserpmoc ssel tlef kciR dna
,snoitcarfni suoires erom rof ygolopa na saw ereht dlot neeb d'eH
.daeh sih koohs dna sdrac sih pu dekcip kciR
,mih rof ecaps a kaens ot deganam wohemos
.anoiF htiw mih tfel dna
.wodniw eht yb llaw eht ot dehcatta saw ksed llams A
,swap owt htiw ,revo ti dnaH
elbirret yleritne leef t'ndid eh taht rovaf llams a ti detnuoc eh tub
,deddon eh dna ,ylteercsid retnuoc eht no yart eht dehcuot krelc eht tub
.senohp rieht ro skoob rieht no desucof demees ytirojam tsav eht dna ,semulov wol ot tpek yeht tub
.eciffo s'tneilc eht sdrawot tuo tes eh sa
.egapbew sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna 1 WALC dna
esiop ssel htiw devom eH
,esruoc fo ,hcihw ,noitatnemucod citats no gniyler tuohtiw ygolopot krowten rieht fo ssenerawa esaercni ot stnaw seirtsudnI yvaeH adekI ,dnatsrednu I tahw morf ,oS"
.ylteiuq mih redisnoc ot deraeppa dna
,tol a llits saw tI
emas eht htiw doof reh kcatta ot nossel reh desuap neht
.koobeton dnuob-rehtael a dna nep a yb dewollof
.moor ecnerefnoc eht ot mih del dna
,ylrae os saw eh debrutrep rehtar saw ksed noitpecer eht ta netram ehT
,thgiarts pu tas ehs dna ,pu dekrep srae reH ".deednI"
wob llams a htiw tekcit sih nekat d'ohw nexiv eht ot yart sih dednah dna pu tog eh os
.niaga dehgual ehS
,eno petS .sekatsim emos edam uoy
"?thgir ,meht htiw stniop emos erocs ot tnaw uoy ,kooL
.ereht tiaw mih tel ehs os ,ytpme dna ydaer saw moor ecnerefnoc eht tub
.feirb ot emit uoy evig t'ndid yllaer ew os ,evitisnes-emit ytterp saw siht ,thgir er'uoy tuB .gniddik m'I"
.nijiag er'uoY ?tahw os tub
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
gal tej eht htiw pleh ot eeffoc rehtona flesmih tog kciR
.pu dnats dnA .ereh s'tneilC
.ti tuoba yrrow t'noD
,eeffoc dennac gnilles saw rotca naciremA railimaf ,derehtaew A
.mih ta daeh reh dekcoc ehS ".nalp
.deraeppasid dna ",ko ,iaH"
.gnimool saw eh ekil tlef eh ,flow llat-toof-xis a sa tub
.mih rof skrow ti erus ekam ot gniog er'uoy dna
.deddon kciR
"?uoy pleh ew yam woH .ris ,gnineve dooG"
.yletaidemmi revo emac namow lesaew ehT "!nesamimuS"
,sregnessap rehto fo sserp eht ni nevE
,noitatneserp sih gniweiver neeb dah eH
,erutnevda fo tirips eht ni ,dna ,railimaf erom saw eeffoc nevE
.sraey eht revo dah d'eh setaicossa wef a ni ralimis gnihtemos nees d'eH
.rotavele eht fo tuo deppets eh litnu tekcit tsafkaerb sih togrof eh ,tsriF
.su gnivah rof uoy knaht ,adekI .rM"
,noitadipert emos htiw ti dehcaorppa kciR
.gnivom detrats niart eht nehw
erus ylbanosaer saw eh etag eht dehcaorppa eh erofeb setunim lareves rof spam yawbus eht dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.wob elttil a evig
.hcnerF ni troper swen a ot gninetsil eb ot demees mih raen enoemoS
.daeh reh koohs ehS
.ytilanosrep esnetni reh htiw llew deriap dna
,nus eht erofeb tsuj pU
.ruf dettam-levart eht tuo gnihtooms dna lautir railimaf eht ni trofmoc gnikat
"!usamiazog oiahO"
.daeh sih koohs eH ".noitpo
.rehto eht ot rood moorhtab eht dna
.ereh em tnes dna PTR ni boj ym fo tuo em derih hcum ytterp uoY .oN"
segasuas htiw og ot ecir saw erehT .tnereffid
.retteb hcuM" .dennirg ehS